Resistance is futile.
You will disarm your weapons
and escort us to Sector 001.
If you attempt to intervene,
we will destroy you.
Red Alert.
Load all torpedo bays,
ready phasers.
Move us to position alpha,
Ensign.
They've locked on.
Reroute auxiliary power.
Our shields are being drained!
64 percent...
42...
Recalibrate shield nutation.
Modulation is having no effect.
Shields have failed!
Full reverse.
Maintain all!
Damage report.
Damage report!
Warning. Damage to warp core.
Containment failure
in five minutes.
Direct hit...
decks one through four...
Let's get the civilians
to the escape pods, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Leave everything.
Get to your assigned
evacuation area now!
Warning. Damage to warp core.
Containment failure
in four minutes.
Dora!
I'll take care of her.
You go on.
Have you seen Jennifer?
Jennifer?!
Jake!
Warning. Damage to warp core.
Containment failure
in three minutes.
I'm going to get your mom.
You're going to be okay.
Jennifer!
Okay, Jake.
We'll get your mom out,
and we'll get out of here.
Commander!
Help me!
Jennifer... hold on.
Sir...
Just help me to get her free!
She's gone.
There's nothing we can do.
We have to leave!
Warning. Damage to warp core.
Containment failure
in two minutes.
Ensign, take the boy.
Aye, sir.
We've got to go now, sir.
Damn it!
We just can't leave her here!
Oh! Oh, no!
Jake, Jake, you're okay.
Stand by to launch.
Ready.
Jake.
There you are.
How are they biting?
Small-fries.
Threw them back.
Want to go for a swim?
Don't have time.
We have to get ready.
It won't be so bad.
I've heard that Bajor
is a beautiful world.
So why can't we
live on the planet
instead of some
old space station?
The station is
in orbit of Bajor.
It will be just like shore duty.
Will there be kids there?
Absolutely!
Lots of kids.
Bridge to Sisko.
Yes, Captain?
We're approaching
Deep Space 9, Commander.
We'll be docking
in seven minutes.
Acknowledged.
Come on.
What do you say?
We'll take the pond with us.
Computer, end program.
Is that it?
Commence Station Log,
Deep Space 9
Commander Benjamin Sisko,
Stardate 46388.2.
At the request of the Bajoran
provisional government
Starfleet has agreed
to establish
a Federation presence
in this system
following the withdrawal
of the Cardassian
occupational forces.
The first contingent of officers
including my Chief
of Operations, Miles O'Brien
arrived two days ago
on the Enterprise.
I'm told the Cardassians
decided to have some fun
the day they left.
Four Bajorans were killed
trying to protect their shops.
Why hasn't anybody
cleaned this up?
We've got
all available personnel
assigned to repairing
primary systems, sir.
The Cardassians took
every component of value.
We're virtually defenseless.
I discussed this
with Major Kira
the attaché assigned here by
the Bajoran government and...
Understood.
What about the civilians
who operated these shops?
A lot of them lost
everything they had.
A few are trying to rebuild
but most are
packing up to leave.
Welcome, Commander.
Please enter.
The Prophets await you.
Another time, perhaps.
Another time.
When my wife Keiko
saw our quarters
she started talking
about visiting her mother
in Kumomoto.
Sir, I wouldn't allow
the boy to go roaming.
We're still having
some security problems.
Dad, there is nothing
to sleep on in there
except for a cushion
on the floor.
Well, we can get
you a real bunk
off the Enterprise.
I almost forgot.
Captain Picard wants to see you
as soon as possible.
He does?
Any word on our science
and medical officers yet?
They're expected tomorrow.
Jake, I want you to stay here
till I come back.
Is this the food replicator?
I'm afraid they're all off-line.
There's plenty
of emergency rations.
I could send some down.
Dad...
We're going to have to rough it
until we get things
up and running, Jake, okay?
Okay.
"Okay."
I'd like to ask the designer
what he was thinking about
when they built this place.
I still haven't been able
to find an ODN access.
That's the Prefect's
office up there.
So all others have
to look up with respect.
Cardassian architecture.
Yes, sir.
Major Kira's been using it.
Is it my imagination
or is it unusually warm?
The environmental controls
in Ops are stuck at 32 C.
We're working on it.
I guess it's time
to meet Major Kira.
Sir, have you ever served
with any Bajoran women?
No. Why?
I was just wondering, sir.
They've become meaningless.
I just don't agree, Kira.
You are throwing it all away.
All of you!
You're being a fool!
Well, then don't ask
my opinion next time.
Yes?
I'm Benjamin Sisko.
I suppose you want the office.
Well, I thought
I'd say hello first
and then take the office
but we could do it
in any order you'd like.
Hello.
Is something bothering you,
Major?
You don't want to ask me that,
Commander.
Why not?
Because I have the bad habit
of telling the truth
even when people
don't want to hear it.
Perhaps I want to hear it.
I don't believe the Federation
has any business being here.
The provisional government
disagrees with you.
The provisional government and I
don't agree on a lot of things
which is probably
why they sent me
to this godforsaken place.
I have been fighting
for Bajoran independence
since I was old enough
to pick up a phaser.
We finally drive
the Cardassians out
and what do our new leaders do?
They call up the Federation
and invite them right in!
The Federation
is only here to help...
...Help us.
Yes, I know.
The Cardassians said
the same thing 60 years ago.
Major, when I was ordered here
I requested a Bajoran national
as my First Officer.
It made sense.
It still does, at least to me.
Now, you and I are going to have
to find some way to...
Yes, Major?
Odo, are you reading something
at A-14?
My security array
has been down for two hours.
I'll meet you there.
We've been having
a lot of break-ins lately.
No need for you
to come along, Commander.
Hurry up!
Now!
All right!
Just stand where you are!
Hold it!
That's enough!
Who the hell are you?
Odo, this is our new
Starfleet Commander.
I don't allow weapons
on the Promenade.
That includes phasers.
Nog?
What's going on?
The boy's in a lot of trouble.
Commander, my name is Quark.
I used to run the local
gambling establishment.
This is my brother's boy.
Surely, you can see
he has only...
a peripheral involvement
in all this.
We're scheduled
to depart tomorrow.
If we could be permitted
to take him
I promise you,
he will be severely...
That won't be possible.
Take him to the brig.
Quark probably
sent the two of them here
to steal the ore samples
in the first place.
Major, there's a
Ferengi legal tradition.
It's called plea bargaining.
I might let the boy go
but I want something
in exchange from Mr. Quark...
something very important.
O'Brien to Commander Sisko.
Go ahead.
Sir, the Enterprise
hailed us again.
Captain Picard
is waiting to see you.
Acknowledged.
This won't take long.
Come.
Commander, yes, please come in.
Welcome to Bajor.
It's been a long time, Captain.
Have we met before?
Yes, sir.
We met in battle.
I was on the Saratoga
at Wolf 359.
I assume
that you have been briefed
on the events leading
to the Cardassian withdrawal.
Yes, sir.
I understand they spent
the last half century
robbing the planet
of every valuable resource
before abandoning it.
They've left the Bajorans
without a means
of being self-sustaining.
The relief efforts
we've been coordinating
are barely adequate.
I...
I've come to know the Bajorans.
I'm... a strong proponent
for their entry
into the Federation.
Is it going to happen?
Not easily.
The ruling parties are
at each other's throats.
Factions that were united
against the Cardassians
have resumed old conflicts.
Sounds like they're not ready.
Your job is to do everything
short of violating
the Prime Directive
to make sure that they are.
I have been...
made aware by Starfleet
of your objections
to this assignment.
I... I would have thought
that after three years spent
at the Utopia Planitia Yards
that you would be
ready for a change.
I have a son
that I'm raising alone, Captain.
This is not
the ideal environment.
Unfortunately,
as Starfleet officers
we do not always have the luxury
to serve
in an ideal environment.
I realize that, sir
and I'm investigating
the possibility
of returning to Earth
for civilian service.
Then perhaps Starfleet Command
should be considering
a replacement for you.
That's probably a good idea.
I'll look into it.
In the meantime, however...
In the meantime,
I will do the job
I've been ordered to do
to the best of my ability, sir.
Dismissed.
It's really quite simple, Quark.
You're not going to leave.
Not going to leave?
But we're packed
and ready to go.
Unpack.
I don't understand, Commander.
Why would you want me to stay?
I'm curious myself.
The man is a gambler
and a thief.
I'm not a thief.
You are a thief.
If I am, you haven't
been able to prove it
for four years.
Please.
My officers,
the Bajoran engineers
all their families
depend on the shops
and services of this Promenade.
If people like you abandon it
this is going to become
a ghost town.
We need someone
to step forward and say
"I'm staying.
I'm rebuilding."
We need a community leader
and it's going to be...
you, Quark.
Community leader.
Seems reasonable.
You have all the character
references of a politician.
How could I possibly
operate my establishment
under Starfleet
rules of conduct?
This is still a Bajoran station.
We're just here to administrate.
You run honest games
you won't have any problems
from me.
Commander, I've made a career
out of knowing when to leave
and this Bajoran
provisional government
is far too provisional
for my taste
and when governments fall
people like me
are lined up and shot.
There is that risk...
but, then,
you are a gambler, Quark.
And a thief.
You know, Quark, that poor boy
is about to spend
the best years of his life
in a Bajoran prison.
I'm a father myself.
I know what your brother
must be going through.
The boy should be
with his family
not in some cold jail cell.
Think about it.
It's up to you.
You know, at first
I didn't think
I was going to like him.
Major?
Everyone else is busy
repairing the primary systems.
I suppose Starfleet officers
aren't used to getting
their hands dirty.
In the refugee camps
we learned to do
whatever needed to be done.
Didn't matter who you were.
I was just talking
with our good neighbor, Quark.
He's laying odds
that the government's
going to fall.
Quark knows a good bet
when he hears one.
This government
will be gone in a week
and so will you.
What happens to Bajor then?
Civil war.
You think it's inevitable?
The only one who can prevent it
is Opaka.
Opaka?
Our spiritual leader.
She's known as the Kai.
Our religion
is the only thing that
holds my people together.
If she would call
for unity, they'd listen.
Leaders of all the factions
have tried to get to her
but she lives in seclusion
rarely sees anyone.
Commander...
it is time.
I apologize for the condition
in which we greet you.
The Cardassians?
Your arrival has been
greatly anticipated.
Have you ever explored
your pagh, Commander?
Pagh?
A Bajoran draws courage
from his spiritual life.
Our life-force...
our pagh...
is replenished by the Prophets.
Breathe.
Kai Opaka,
if we could discuss...
Breathe!
Ironic.
One who does not wish to be
among us is to be the Emissary.
Please, come with me.
You are correct that Bajor
is in great jeopardy
but it is the threat
to our spiritual life
that far outweighs any other.
Perhaps, but I am powerless
until...
Commander.
I cannot give you
what you deny yourself.
I'm sorry?
Look for solutions
from within, Commander.
Come with me.
What is it?
The Tear of the Prophet.
What the hell?
Opaka?
Ah... ow!
Hey!
I'm sorry.
It's just that this...
Jen?
Yes?
Jennifer?
I'm sorry.
Did we meet last night
at George's party?
George?
Jennifer...
Wait a minute.
This is impossible.
Are you okay?
I know this place.
This is Gilgo Beach,
where we met.
We met here before?
I was carrying
three lemonades...
The sand was burning my feet
and I stopped here... to...
Ow!
Do you realize
how incredible this is?
No, of course you don't.
Jennifer...
have a lemonade.
I'm afraid I don't accept drinks
from strange men on the beach.
So tell me the truth.
Have we really met before?
No.
Then how do you know my name?
I... uh...
George told me
at the party.
Are you going
to tell me your name?
Oh, Ben Sisko.
I just graduated
from Starfleet Academy.
I'm waiting
for my first posting.
Oh, a junior officer.
Yeah.
My mother warned me
to watch out
for junior officers.
Your mother is
going to adore me.
You're awfully sure of yourself.
It's not every day
you meet the girl
you're going to marry.
Do you use this routine
a lot with women?
No, never before,
and never again.
Sure.
How about letting me
cook dinner for you tonight?
My father was a gourmet chef.
I will make for you
his famous aubergine stew.
I don't know.
You're supposed to say, "Yes!"
I'll probably be sorry.
Jennifer!
Nine Orbs, like this one,
have appeared in the skies
over the past 10,000 years.
The Cardassians
took the others.
You must find
the Celestial Temple
before they do.
The Celestial Temple?
Tradition says the Orbs
were sent by the Prophets
to teach us.
What we have learned
has shaped our theology.
The Cardassians will do anything
to decipher their powers.
If they discover
the Celestial Temple
they could destroy it.
What makes you think
I can find your temple?
This will help you.
Kai Opaka...
I can't unite my people
till I know the Prophets
have been warned.
You will find the Temple...
not for Bajor,
not for the Federation
but for your own pagh.
It is quite simply, Commander
the journey you have
always been destined to take.
What?
I was just thinking...
how much you look like your mom.
Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead.
Sorry to disturb you,
Commander
but there's something on the
Promenade you might want to see.
On my way.
Step up, step up.
Fortune's fates
are with you today, friends.
Dabo!
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
That's fine.
I'll be right back.
What will you have, Commander?
How's the local synthale?
You won't like it.
I love the Bajorans.
Such a deeply spiritual culture
but they make a dreadful ale.
Never trust ale
from a god-fearing people
or a Starfleet Commander
that has one
of your relatives in jail.
Dabo!
Station Log, Stardate 46390.1.
The Enterprise has been ordered
to the Lapolis system.
They're scheduled to depart
at 0500 hours
after off-loading
three runabout-class vessels.
Meanwhile, our medical
and science officers
are arriving,
and I'm looking forward
to a reunion
with a very old friend.
Commander, if you'd like me
to give them a tour
of the station...
You and Dr. Bashir go ahead.
I'm afraid I have to put
Lieutenant Dax
to work right away.
Jadzia...
uh...
maybe we could...
get together later for dinner...
or... or... or...
or a... or a drink?
I'd be delighted.
He's a little young
for you, isn't he?
He's 27. I'm 28.
328, maybe.
Did you tell him about
that slug inside of you?
Yes, Benjamin.
He knows I'm a Trill.
He finds it fascinating.
He's never met
a joined species before.
I wonder if he'd
been as fascinated
if you still looked
the way you did
the last time I saw you.
Perhaps not.
Whew.
This is going to take
some getting used to.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm still the same old Dax...
more or less.
I'm afraid we've had
some security problems.
Looks like looters
got in here.
Oh, this will be perfect.
Real...
frontier medicine.
Frontier medicine?
Major, I had my choice
of any job in the fleet.
Did you?
I didn't want some cushy job
or a research grant.
I wanted this...
the farthest reaches
of the galaxy.
One of the most remote
outposts available.
This is where the adventure is.
This is where heroes are made.
Right here,
in the wilderness.
This "wilderness" is my home.
Well, I-I-I didn't mean...
The Cardassians left behind
a lot of injured people,
Doctor.
You can make yourself useful
by bringing
your Federation medicine
to the natives.
Oh, you'll find them
a friendly, simple folk.
We do have one advantage.
The monks have been studying
these things for 10,000 years.
I've had our computers set up
to interface with their
historical data banks.
That should give us something.
Soon as possible, Dax.
The eight other Orbs
are probably in some
Cardassian laboratory
being turned upside down
and inside out.
Benjamin...
I was happy when I heard
you accepted this assignment.
I'd been worried about you.
It's good to see you, too...
old man.
Computer, create a data base
for all historical references
to the Orbs
including all reports
of any unexplained phenomena
in Bajoran space.
Time parameters?
Ten millennia.
Initializing data base.
Requested function will require
two hours to complete.
Curzon.
The Captain's
in the ready room, Chief.
Should I tell him you're here?
Oh, that's okay.
Thanks.
Transport me
to the Ops pad, Maggie.
Yes, sir.
Mr. O'Brien?
I understand that I just
missed you on the Bridge.
Yes, sir.
I... I didn't want
to disturb you, sir.
Ensign.
This is your favorite
transporter room, isn't it?
Number three, yes, sir.
You know, yesterday
I called down here
and I asked for you
without thinking.
It won't be quite the same.
It's just
a transporter room, sir.
Permission to disembark,
Captain.
Permission granted.
Energize.
Message coming in
from their Commander
Gul Dukat.
Dukat.
He used to be the Cardassian
Prefect of Bajor.
He's requesting permission
to come aboard to greet us.
Surely a coincidence
that the Enterprise just left.
Mr. O'Brien
tell Gul Dukat
I look forward to meeting him.
Good day, Commander.
Gul Dukat.
Excuse my presumption
but... this was my office
only two weeks ago.
I'm not used to being
on this side of the desk.
I'll be honest with you,
Commander.
I miss this office.
I was not happy to leave it.
Drop by any time
you're feeling homesick.
You are very gracious.
And allow me to assure
you that we only want
to be helpful
in this difficult transition.
You're far
from the Federation fleet
alone in this remote outpost
with poor defense systems.
Your Cardassian neighbors
will be quick to respond
to any problems you might have.
We'll try to keep the dog
off your lawn.
So... tell me,
what did you think of Kai Opaka?
I know you went
to the surface to see her.
I understand
you brought back an Orb.
We thought we had all of them.
Perhaps we could have
an exchange of information...
pool our resources.
I don't know anything
about an Orb.
We will be in close proximity
should you wish
to reconsider my suggestion.
In the meantime
I assume you have no objection
to my men
enjoying the hospitality
of the Promenade.
Commander.
What do you know
about the Denorios Belt?
Your basic charged
plasma field...
no one gets anywhere near it
unless they have to.
In the 22nd century,
a ship carrying Kai Taluno
was disabled for several
days in the Denorios Belt
where he claims
he had a vision.
Let me guess.
He saw the Celestial Temple
of the Prophets.
Not quite.
But he did say
that the heavens opened up
and nearly swallowed his ship.
Are we reduced to chasing
metaphors to solve this?
That's not all.
At least five of the Orbs
were found in the Denorios Belt.
There were also 23 navigational
reports over the years
of unusually severe
neutrino disturbances
in the same area.
I've correlated
all these reports
into one analysis grid.
Our Celestial Temple?
Worth a look...
but we've got Cardassians
on our back doorstep.
We need to get by them
undetected.
May we have
your attention please.
This establishment
is being closed.
What do you mean?
You can't do this.
If you have a problem, sir
you'll have to take it up
with Commander Sisko.
I intend to.
This is outrageous.
Friends, my apologies.
A minor misunderstanding
that will be rectified shortly.
Give them something
to put their winnings into.
Because we were winning
too much, of course.
Leave it to Starfleet
to ruin a fine day.
Rio Grande to Ops.
Initializing prelaunch systems.
Confirmed, Rio Grande.
Scanners are picking up
fluctuations
in the Cardassian's
energy distribution net.
Their computers are crashing.
Shields and sensors are down.
Odo's done it.
Ops to Rio Grande.
You're in business.
Beginning launch sequence.
Odo's reached
the transport site.
Trying to lock on.
I've never done this
with a Cardassian transporter.
Damn it, what's the problem?
Nice work, Constable.
Approaching grid perimeter.
Slowing
to one-quarter impulse.
Computer, give me visual,
bearing 23 mark 217.
Range... 3,100 kilometers.
Sensors are picking up
unusually high proton counts.
Setting a new course
to those coordinates.
All external wave intensities
are increasing rapidly
but checking...
Confirmed. There is no
corresponding increase
inside the cabin.
How is that possible?
Sensors are not functioning.
We've lost all contact
with the space station.
Scanners are reading
major subspace disruption
at their last known coordinates.
What the hell is happening
out there?
I don't know.
They're just gone.
Are your navigational readings
going crazy?
I'll recalibrate
when I have a moment.
Take your time.
Can you get a fix
on our coordinates?
There is a star
just under
five light years away.
No M-Class planets.
Computer, identify
closest star system.
Idran... a ternary system
consisting
of twin O-type companions.
Idran?
That can't be right.
Computer,
basis of identification?
Idran is based
on the analysis conducted
in the 22nd century
by the Quadros-1 probe
of the Gamma Quadrant.
The Gamma Quadrant?!
70,000 light years from Bajor?
I'd say we just found our way
into a wormhole.
It's not like any wormhole
I've ever seen.
There were none
of the usual resonance waves.
Could this be how the Orbs
found their way
into the Bajoran system?
Not an unreasonable hypothesis.
If it's true
that would mean that this
has been here for 10,000 years.
Dax, we might
have just discovered
the first stable wormhole
known to exist.
Bring us about, Lieutenant.
I'm modifying the flight
program to compensate
for the spatial
discontinuities.
We should have
a smoother ride this time.
Did you reduce impulse power?
No. Why?
We're losing velocity.
Forward velocity
down to 80 kph.
Warning.
Impulse system overload.
Auto shutdown in 12 seconds.
Disengaging engines.
Velocity at 20 kph.
I'm picking up atmosphere.
Inside a wormhole?
Capable of supporting life.
We've just landed.
On what?
It's beautiful.
You have a strange
eye for beauty, Dax.
You don't think this is one
of the most idyllic settings
you've ever seen?
We are standing on a rock face.
Do you see the storms?
It's as clear as a summer's day.
You see it, too?
Yes.
Low-level ionic pattern.
It's probing us.
Someone's idea
of shaking hands maybe.
I am Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the United Federation
of Planets.
Dax!
Another neutrino disruption.
Scanners are
picking up an object
near their last
known coordinates.
It isn't a ship.
Major, there's something
inside it...
some kind of life-form.
Are the Cardassian
sensors picking it up?
They should be
back on line by now.
We have to assume they
know everything we know.
Yellow Alert.
Secure Ops.
Beam it aboard, Mr. O'Brien
but put it in a level-1
security field.
Aye, sir.
Locking on.
Who are you?
Who are you?!
It is corporeal!
A physical entity.
What?
What did you say?
It is responding
to visual and auditory stimuli.
Linguistic communication.
Yes, linguistic communication.
Are you capable
of communicating with me?
What... are you?
My species is known as human.
I come from a planet
called Earth.
Earth?
This is what my planet
looks like.
You and I
are very different species.
It will take... time
for us to understand
one another.
What is this... time?
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 46392.7.
We're preparing to launch
a rescue mission
to find Commander Sisko.
But first, our navigational
sensors must be recalibrated
to work under the conditions
reported by Lieutenant Dax.
It is no ordinary wormhole.
My analysis suggests
that it isn't
even a natural phenomenon.
Not natural?
You mean it was constructed?
It's very possible
whoever made the Orbs
also created this wormhole.
The Cardassians
are leaving their position
on a course toward
the Denorios Belt.
Mr. O'Brien
what would it take
to move this station
to the mouth of the wormhole?
This isn't a starship, Major.
We've got six working thrusters
to power us and that's it.
160 million-kilometer
trip would take
two months.
It has to be there tomorrow.
That's not possible, sir.
That wormhole
might just reshape
the future
of this entire quadrant.
The Bajorans have
to stake a claim to it
and I have to admit
that claim would be
a lot stronger
if there's a Federation presence
to back it up.
Couldn't you modify
the subspace field output
of the deflector generators
just enough
to create a low-level field
around the station?
So we could lower
the inertial mass.
If you can make
the station lighter
those six thrusters
will be all the power we need.
This whole station
could break apart like
an egg if it doesn't work.
Even if it does work,
we're still going
to need help from Starfleet
once we get there.
The Enterprise is still
the nearest starship.
They could reach us in two days.
We should advise Starfleet
that we will require
their assistance.
You have Ops, Mr. O'Brien.
Lieutenant, you're with me.
Aye, sir.
You too, Doc.
Time to be a hero.
Yes, sir!
Constable...
This is a security matter.
I'm in charge of security.
Security here, on the station.
I cannot justify taking
you into this wormhole.
We have no idea what we're
dealing with in there.
It could be hostile...
Major, I was found
in the Denorios Belt.
I don't know where I came from...
no idea if there are
any others like me.
All my life, I've been forced
to pass myself off as one of you
always wondering
who I really am.
Well, the answers
to a lot of my questions
may be somewhere on
the other side of that wormhole.
You coming?
The creature must be destroyed
before it destroys us.
It is malevolent.
Aggressive.
Adversarial.
It must be destroyed.
I am not your enemy.
I was sent here by the people
you contacted.
Contacted?
With your devices... your Orbs.
We seek contact
with other life-forms
not corporeal creatures
who annihilate us.
I have not come
to annihilate anyone.
Destroy it now.
My species respects life
above all else.
Can you say the same?
I do not understand the threat
that I bring to you
but I am not your enemy.
Allow me to prove it.
Prove it?
It can be argued
that a human is ultimately
the sum of his experiences.
Experiences...
what is this?
Memories.
Events from my past
like this one.
Past?
Things that happened before now.
You have absolutely no idea
what I'm talking about.
What comes before now
is no different
than what is now,
or what is to come.
It is one's existence.
Then, for you,
there is no linear time.
Linear time... what is this?
My species lives
in one point in time
and once we move
beyond that point
it becomes the past.
The future, all that
is still to come
does not exist yet for us.
Does not exist yet?
That is the nature
of linear existence
and if you examine
it more closely
you will see that you
do not need to fear me.
Partial field established.
Instability at 12%.
Partial field?
Is station's inertial mass
low enough to break orbit?
Procedure is not recommended.
Damn it, I didn't ask
for an opinion.
Just tell me whether or not
we can get enough thrust
with only a partial field
established.
Affirmative.
All right. Thank you.
Initiate transit mode,
three-axis stabilization.
Aye, sir.
Engage thrusters.
Warning.
Field integrity declining.
Instability at 21%.
We've got to close that gap
in the field
or we'll tear ourselves
into a million pieces.
Warning. Subspace field
collapse in 60 seconds.
Computer
transfer energy
from the inertial dampers
to reinforce the subspace field.
Procedure is not recommended.
Damn it, transfer the energy.
Unable to comply.
Level-1 safety protocols
have canceled request.
Canceled it?
Warning. Subspace field
collapse in 30 seconds.
I'm going to transfer it
manually.
On my mark, redirect the flow
to the deflectors
and keep the power balanced.
Aye, sir.
Field collapse in 15 seconds.
Now.
Field energy
now within flight tolerances.
Good work, sir.
Computer, you and I need
to have a little talk.
The Cardassian warship
is in visual range.
On screen.
They're headed right to it.
Well, they've got to listen
to reason, haven't they?
When we warn them what could
happen if they go in there.
Doctor, most people,
in my experience
wouldn't know reason if it
walked up and shook their hand.
You can count Gul Dukat
among them.
This is the Federation
Ship Yangtzee Kiang.
Major Kira Nerys in command.
Yes, Major.
Gul Dukat, we know you're headed
for the wormhole.
Wormhole?
What wormhole is that?
I strongly suggest
you do not proceed.
We encountered
a hostile life-form inside.
Perhaps they will be
less hostile to Cardassians
than to humans.
Dukat
these people are trying
to save you
from a lot of trouble.
Really?
And I suppose
you're going to tell me
that these are not
the life-forms
that have sent the Orbs
or that your Commander Sisko
is not negotiating
for their technology.
I thank you for your concern
but I think we will see
for ourselves.
So much for reason.
Jennifer.
Yes, that was her name.
She is part of your existence.
She is part of my past.
She's no longer alive.
But she is part
of your existence.
She was a most important
part of my existence
but I lost her some time ago.
Lost?
What is this?
In a linear existence,
we can't go back to the past
to get something we left behind
so... it's lost.
It is inconceivable
that any species
could exist in such a manner.
You are deceiving us.
No.
This is the truth.
This day, this...
this park...
it was almost 15 years
ago, far in the past.
It was a day that was
very important to me...
a day that shaped
every day that followed.
That is the essence
of a linear existence.
Each day affects the next.
Listen to it.
To what?
The sound of children playing.
What could be more beautiful?
So you like children.
That almost sounds
like a domestic inquiry.
I've heard Starfleet officers
don't want families
because they complicate
their lives.
Starfleet officers
don't often find mates
who want to raise families
on a starship.
That almost sounds
like a domestic inquiry.
I think it was.
As corporeal entities
humans find physical
touch to cause pleasure.
Pleasure...
what is this?
Good feelings.
Happiness.
But this is your existence.
It's difficult to be here...
more difficult
than any other memory.
Why?
Because...
because this was the day...
that I lost Jennifer.
I don't want to be here.
Then why do you exist here?
I don't understand.
You exist here.
What's wrong?
What's happening?
We should be reaching
the wormhole coordinates
in two minutes.
Slowing to one-third imp...
Are you still there?
What just happened?
More of your kind.
Another ship...
in the wormhole?
Wormhole?
What is this?
It is how we describe
the passage
that brought me here.
It is terminated.
Terminated?
Our existence is disrupted
whenever one of you
enters the passage.
Your linear nature
is inherently destructive.
You have no regard
for the consequences
of your acts.
That's not true.
We're aware that every choice
we make has a consequence.
But you claim you do not know
what it will be.
We don't.
Then how can you take
responsibility
for your actions?
We use past experience
to help guide us.
For Jennifer and me
all the experiences
in our lives
prepared us for the day
we met on the beach...
helped us recognize
that we had a future together.
When we married, we accepted
all the consequences
of that act
whatever they might be
including the consequences
of you.
Me?
My son Jake...
The child with Jennifer.
Yes.
Linear... procreation?
Jake is the continuation
of our family.
The sound of children playing.
Aggressive.
Adversarial.
Competition.
For fun.
It's a game that Jake
and I play on the holodeck.
It's called baseball.
Baseball?
What is this?
I was afraid you'd ask that.
I throw this ball to you
and this other player
stands between us with a bat...
a stick... and he...
and he tries to hit the ball
in between
these two white lines.
Oh.
The rules aren't important.
What's important is...
it's linear.
Every time I throw this ball
a hundred different things
can happen in a game.
He might swing and miss,
he might hit it.
The point is you never know.
You try to anticipate
set a strategy
for all the possibilities
as best you can, but in the end
it comes down to throwing
one pitch after another
and seeing what happens.
With each new consequence,
the game begins to take shape.
And you have no idea
what that shape is
until it is completed.
That's right.
In fact, the game
wouldn't be worth playing
if we knew
what was going to happen.
You value your ignorance
of what is to come?
That may be
the most important thing
to understand about humans.
It is the unknown
that defines our existence.
We are constantly searching
not just for answers
to our questions
but for new questions.
We are explorers.
We explore our lives day by day
and we explore the galaxy
trying to expand
the boundaries of our knowledge
and that is why I am here...
not to conquer you with weapons
or with ideas
but to coexist...
and learn.
If all you say is true
why do you exist here?
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
We've rendezvoused
with the space station
at the former coordinates
of the wormhole.
Unfortunately,
our scans have revealed
no trace of either the wormhole
or Dukat's ship.
A few minutes ago
three Cardassian warships
crossed the border
no doubt on their way
to search for Dukat.
Mr. O'Brien, can you establish
a high-energy thoron field
before they get
into sensor range?
I don't want them
to be able to scan
- our defense systems.
- Aye, sir.
They're hailing us.
On screen.
I am Gul Jasad
of the Cardassian guard,
Seventh Order.
Where is our warship?
With any luck,
they're in the Gamma Quadrant
on the other side
of the wormhole.
What wormhole?
Our sensors show no indication
of a wormhole in this sector.
That's because
it just collapsed.
What?!
We believe it was
artificially created.
That may be why our sensors
never picked up
any of the usual quantum
fluctuation patterns.
You expect me to believe
that someone created a wormhole
and now conveniently
has disassembled it?
That's exactly
what I expect you to believe.
They're flooding subspace
with antilepton interference.
It'll cut off our communications
with Starfleet.
They're powering up
their forward phasers.
Red Alert.
Shields up.
What shields?
They're hailing us again.
Open the channel.
We do not accept
your explanation.
Somehow you have destroyed
our warship.
Gul Jasad, I assure you...
We demand the unconditional
surrender of this space station
or we will open fire.
I need at least a day
to make the necessary
preparations.
You have one hour.
I can transfer
all available power
to establish partial shields
around critical areas
but if they hit the docking ring
we'll sustain heavy damage.
Constable,
if you would coordinate
moving all personnel
to safer locations.
What was the last reported
position of the Enterprise?
At least 20 hours away.
We've got to hold out
till they get here.
I can't believe the Cardassians
would ever attack
a Federation outpost.
Doctor, you ever studied
your military history
of the border wars?
Yes.
Ever heard
of the Setlik III massacre?
I assume, Mr. O'Brien,
you would agree
surrender is not
a preferable option.
You know what they do
to their prisoners, sir.
What is the point of bringing me
back again to this?
We do not bring you here.
You bring us here.
You exist here.
Then give me the power
to lead you somewhere
else... anywhere else.
We cannot give you
what you deny yourself.
Look for solutions from within,
Commander.
I was ready to die with her.
Die... what is this?
The termination
of their linear existence.
We've got to go now, sir.
Damn it!
We just can't leave her here.
Oh! Oh, no!
I never left this ship.
You exist here.
I...
exist here.
I don't know
if you can understand.
I see her like this
every time I close my eyes.
In the darkness...
in the blink of an eye
I see her like this.
None of your past experiences
helped prepare you
for this consequence.
And I have never figured out
how to live without her.
So you choose to exist here.
It is not linear.
No.
It's not linear.
Oh...
Their lead ship is hailing us.
Gul Jasad wants an answer.
Are you ready, Mr. O'Brien?
Yes, sir.
When they penetrate
our thoron field
it should raise a few
eyebrows over there.
All right, then,
let's give them our answer.
Fire six photon torpedoes
across Jasad's bow.
We only have six photons, Major.
We're not going to win this
battle with torpedoes, Chief.
Aye, sir.
An urgent hail from Jasad.
Looks like we got his attention.
On screen.
This is your answer?
You don't think
Starfleet took command
of this space station
without the ability
to defend it, do you?
Defend it?
Your space station
could not defend itself
against one Cardassian warship.
You're probably right, Jasad...
and if you were dealing
with a Starfleet officer
they'd probably admit
we have a hopeless cause here
but I am just a Bajoran
who's been fighting
a hopeless cause
against the Cardassians
all her life.
So if you want a war...
I'll give you one.
Major.
Remind me never
to get into a game
of Roladan Wild Draw with you.
They were using a thoron field
to block our sensors
but we were able
to penetrate it.
What are their defenses?
According to our scans,
an estimated 5,000 photons
integrated phaser banks
on all levels.
When did they receive
these armaments?
And how did they install
them without our knowledge?
Somehow they have created
a massive illusion
of duranium shadows.
What if it is not an illusion?
It is.
Why risk the confrontation?
The Fourth Order
can be here in a day.
So can Starfleet.
Their lead ship is sending out
a subspace message
asking for reinforcements.
Yes!
Too soon for
a victory celebration, Doctor.
Mr. O'Brien?
The ships are being deployed
in a standard
attack formation, sir.
Battle stations.
Quickly, now.
Calmly, calmly.
Come along.
They may just be testing us.
I could run a pulse
compression wave
through the phaser banks...
put out a blast that will
make them think twice.
Do it.
Damage report.
Direct hit, level 14.
Empty storage bays.
No casualties.
Shields down to 27%.
A fuel conduit
has ruptured on the Promenade.
Can you divert
the main power flow?
The controls are locked.
Odo to Ops.
Go ahead.
I've got wounded people
down here!
Have you seen that Doctor
of yours anywhere?
I'm on my way.
I'm going to have to shut down
the primary power flow
or the whole Promenade
will go up.
Bloody Cardassians!
I just got the damn thing fixed.
Press there, hard.
Look, Doctor, maybe I should
find you someone...
Hold it there.
That should do it for a while.
Shields are at 18% and falling.
I might still be able
to give you
one more phaser blast, Major.
No.
Signal the lead Cardassian ship
that we will proceed with...
Major...
I'm picking up
a huge neutrino disturbance
15 kilometers
off the forward docking ring.
It's the wormhole.
On screen.
Hail the lead ship.
What did I tell you, Jasad?
There's your wormhole!
Rio Grande to DS9.
On screen.
Go ahead, Commander.
Sorry to be late, Major.
Our friend Gul Dukat
had some problems
on the other side
of the wormhole.
I see you've had
a few of your own.
A few, Commander.
Gul Dukat is signaling
his ships to disarm.
Clear me for docking,
Mr. O'Brien.
Aye, sir.
Cleared for Pad C.
Casualties?
13 injured, Commander,
and no fatalities.
Jake!
Dad!
Station Log,
Commander Benjamin Sisko
Stardate 46393.1.
The life-forms
who created the wormhole
have agreed
to allow safe passage
for all ships traveling
to the Gamma Quadrant.
With the arrival
of the Enterprise
the Cardassians
have left the area.
I suspect that the sight
of their warship
being towed
by a Federation runabout
took the heart
out of their fight.
We're not done
with the Cardassians yet...
not with the strategic
importance of that wormhole.
Well, you've put Bajor
on the map, Commander.
This will shortly become
a leading center of commerce
and of scientific exploration
and for Starfleet,
one of our most important posts.
Captain,
regarding our conversation
about someone to replace me...
Yes, I'm sorry
I haven't had time yet
to communicate that to Command.
I would prefer you ignore it,
sir.
I'm not sure that I can.
Are you certain
that's what you want?
Because we cannot afford to have
a commanding officer who is...
I'm certain, sir.
Good luck, Mr. Sisko.
So, where can someone practice
with his phaser around here?
New rules?
You can't cheat every customer
who walks through the door
anymore, Quark.
You are a community leader now.
Very well, very well.
Perhaps we could discuss
these new rules over a drink.
If you don't take
that hand off my hip
you'll never be able
to raise a glass with it again.
Oh, I love a woman in uniform.
...and three Frunalian
Science Vessels
are requesting
permission to dock.
Problem is we've been
retrofitting the air locks, sir.
Half of them were damaged
during the move
and most of the others
when the Cardassians
blew out the fuel conduits.
I guess they'll just have
to transport aboard...