Do you need me, Julian?
How did you know it was me?
There are different ways
to recognize someone.
The rhythm of their steps,
for example.
You are remarkable.
Julian, you and I
need to have a talk
about Trills and relationships.
Fine.
We'll do it over supper.
Quark has found me this
delightfully dry champagne
estate bottled on Korris I.
Julian...
What is this?
An Altonian brain teaser.
A brain teaser?
A puzzle.
A puzzle?
Mmm.
I love puzzles.
How does it work?
It responds
to neural theta waves.
The goal is to turn the sphere
into a solid color.
And that's all?
That's all.
I've been trying to master it
on and off for, oh, 140 years.
Would you care to try?
Yes.
Just sit comfortably.
And release your tension
into my hands.
Your hands, they're cold.
It's a peculiarity
of the Trill.
Cold hands, warm heart.
Concentrate on the sphere.
Clear your mind.
This requires focus
and clarity of thought.
I understand completely.
What is that exotic scent
you're wearing?
Focus
and clarity of thought.
Yes, yes, I have it.
I'm going to release it
to you now, okay?
Okay.
Computer...
transfer control
to second player.
I think your mind is still
a little busy, Julian.
Wel... So, are you
free for supper?
Ready, Dax?
Sorry.
Perhaps another time.
Maybe you'd like to try again.
Doctor.
Computer...
reset.
Business is good, Quark.
You're almost making
an honest living.
A lot of new faces.
Hmm.
The wormhole does bring
them our way, doesn't it?
Everyone wants a piece
of the new frontier.
And I'm sure you've
already tried
to sell it to a few of them.
We made the decision together.
That's not true.
What?
You decided and asked
me to agree with it.
Grapevine says Chief O'Brien
and the missus
are having problems.
I'll never understand
the humanoid need to...
couple.
You've never... coupled?
Choose not to.
Too many compromises.
You want to watch the
Karo-Net tournament.
She wants to listen to music.
So, you compromise.
You listen to music.
You like Earth jazz.
She prefers Klingon opera.
So, you compromise.
You listen to Klingon opera.
So, here you were
ready to have a nice night
watching the Karo-Net match
and you wind up spending
an agonizing evening
listening to Klingon opera.
That's exactly...
Keiko, sit down.
I didn't mean...
What could they
be going on about
like that, anyway?
She doesn't like it here.
Mmm. Who does?
Ah...
Don't even think about it.
I can so think about it.
You might as well try
to find a drink of water
on the Yadozi Desert.
Besides, I'd say
our new Commander
is interested in her.
Not at all.
I know for a fact
that when she was a he
you know...
before she got this new body...
they were old friends.
Things change.
All right, now here we go.
How long has he been here?
All right, one more time.
He came in on a transport
last night.
Oh...
Something to eat?
Just steamed azna.
Well, some things
are still the same.
If you'd listen to me
you would eat
steamed azna, too.
Dax, did I ever tell you
about the meals
my father used to cook for us
when we were children?
All the time.
Every night in my house,
my dad insisted
that we have supper together
as a family.
He would try out
his new recipes on us.
He used to call us
his test tasters.
Steamed azna would put
years on your life.
Dax, I don't want years
on my life
if I can only eat steamed azna.
Sautéed...
rolloped, fricasseed... fine.
But not steamed.
I've missed your steamed azna.
You must miss Curzon, too.
He was...
you were, are...
a mentor,
another father to me.
This happens to Trills,
Benjamin.
Sometimes our friendships
with other species don't survive
because of the change.
It won't be that way with us.
It's just a little uncomfortable
right now.
I suggest
that you allow yourself
to feel comfortable
with your discomfort.
Time can do the rest.
I don't want to talk
about this anymore.
Keiko...
Dabo!
All right.
I don't want you
on this station.
Yeah, well, that's too bad
because I have
every right to be here.
I decide who has rights
and who doesn't
on this Promenade.
You better ask your Federation
superiors about that one.
I don't have to check
with anyone.
You have 26 hours
to get off this station.
Look, I'm willing
to ask for a transfer
if that will make you happy.
That's not fair either.
You'd have to give up
your promotion.
Not necessarily.
I wish I knew
the right thing to do.
I'm just lost here.
Starfleet doesn't need
a botanist on this station.
Keiko, there's
a whole new quadrant
on the other side
of the wormhole
full of new plant life
to explore.
And ships going to explore it
and I'm not on any of them.
We'll be sending runabouts
through the wormhole.
I'll see to it you get to go.
I don't need favors from you.
I just need to be useful.
Just think how much
more attractive
this place could be
if you planted
some trees and flowers
in the Promenade.
You could even
create an arboretum
from the new specimens
we bring back
from the Gamma Quadrant.
Do you really want
to raise your daughter
in this place, Miles?
Kira to O'Brien.
Go ahead.
We have a nonfunctional power
transfer grid on level five.
All of the upper docking pylons
are out of commission.
On my way.
Hi!
What do you want, hu-man?
My name's Jake.
I know who you are.
What's yours?
Why do you care?
Not exactly a lot of friends
to choose from around here.
You know what I mean.
Nog.
My name is Nog.
His name is Ibudan.
He used to run
black market goods through here
to the surface
during the Cardassian occupation
gouging his fellow men
who needed medical supplies
and so forth.
Some Bajorans actually
considered him a hero
but I saw him let a child die
when the parents couldn't afford
the drug that would have
saved her life.
A few years back, he killed
a Cardassian officer
who wanted a payoff
to look the other way.
He went to prison for murder.
I sent him there.
For murder?
What's he doing out?
The provisional government
let him go.
Killing a Cardassian
isn't considered
much of a crime nowadays.
Doesn't sound like there's
much we can do about it.
I can get him off my Promenade.
If he hasn't done anything wrong
you can't just arbitrarily
force him to leave.
Watch me.
Mr. Odo
you're not going to take the law
into your own hands.
The law?
Commander, laws change
depending on who's making them.
Cardassians one day,
Federation the next.
But justice is justice
and as long as I'm
in charge of secur...
If you can't work
within the rules
I'll find someone who can.
What are they?
Garanian bolites.
Come on!
I guess I know
the competition now.
What are you talking
about, Julian?
Well, did you have a nice dinner
with Commander Sisko?
Julian, Trills do not
look for romance
the same way humans do.
In fact, we find it
quite a nuisance.
A nuisance?
It's a weakness of the young,
and although a Trill host
may have these...
feelings occasionally
it is our wish
to live on a higher plane
to try to rise above
these kinds of temptations.
You said "try to rise above"
which suggests you
don't always succeed.
Julian...
Sisko to Dr. Bashir.
Go ahead.
We need medical assistance
above the bar in Holosuite Four.
Acknowledged, Commander.
I still have that champagne.
On ice.
Are you done with your shift?
Gym's not open tonight.
Help us!
Somebody help us!
Something is happening to us!
Get a doctor!
The door opened only twice.
The first time when the computer
logged Ibudan's check-in
at 1700 hours, 16 minutes.
The suite was secured,
so no one else could enter.
He ran Lauriento massage
holoprogram #101A.
13 minutes later
the door was opened
for the second time
but since Ibudan
obviously didn't exit
we have to assume
that's when the killer left.
Any evidence of a beam-in
during those 13 minutes?
No.
Well then,
how did the killer get in?
He might have
entered the holosuite
the same time Ibudan did.
Cause of death's no mystery.
The knife was thrust
directly between the left
and right thoracic vertebrae
perforating the lower ventricle
of the heart.
The murderer apparently
had a decent knowledge
of Bajoran anatomy.
Doctor, I want you
to look for evidence
that could establish
that someone was
in here with him.
I'll do a sweep
for hair follicles
any skin or cellular
remnants and DNA fragments.
How many ships have
left since yesterday?
Hmm, two.
A Federation survey ship
and a Vulcan science vessel.
Advise all ships in dock
that departures will be delayed
until further notice.
And they were just looking
for trouble.
Those kids had no reason to be
hanging around the Promenade.
It's about the only place
they have to go.
We can't keep them
locked in their rooms.
This isn't like a starship,
Miles.
The kind of freedom children
have on the Enterprise
just won't work
on a space station.
There are too many ways to get
into serious trouble here.
What this place needs
is a school.
All ships have been informed
of the delays, Commander.
Major, do you know
Mr. Zayra, who operates
the Transit Aid Center?
We've met.
He was just telling me
something disturbing.
I think you should hear it.
It's just that the murdered man,
lbudan...
I spoke to him yesterday
about an hour
before it happened.
Where was this?
Quark's.
By the dabo table.
It was after his struggle
with the shape-shifter.
He told me that he was scared.
He was afraid
that Odo would kill him.
There isn't a more honorable man
on this station
than the Constable.
Maybe so.
All I know is, an hour
later, Ibudan was dead.
Computer, lights.
This was Ibudan's quarters.
Feel free to look around.
Double accommodations?
That's what he requested
but only one passenger
was logged in.
He probably just wanted
larger quarters.
If there's anything
else you need...
I want a record of all
the passengers on board.
Of course.
I'll get you a copy
of the ship's manifest.
Computer, how many entries
made from this terminal
during the last 78 hours?
Seven entries noted
in personal calendar files.
Show them to me.
Take me to Stardate 46384.
You won't get any argument
from me, Mrs. O'Brien.
When I heard what happened
this morning on the Promenade...
We weren't doing anything.
I don't want to talk
about this now.
It's this Ferengi boy, Nog...
Jake won't be having
anything more to do with him.
He's the only one here
even close to my age.
That's not exactly true, Jake.
There are 12 other children
on board
ranging from eight to 16.
The problem is, there's
no structured activity for them.
Don't you miss the schools
you used to go to, Jake?
No... I guess.
Studying alone
on the computer...
it kind of gets
boring sometimes.
You know, I've never actually
been a teacher, Commander
but it's something I've
always thought about doing.
As a Starfleet Commander
and a father
I think it's a terrific idea.
What do you need?
Uh...
some space.
We'll find it.
Computers?
You'll have them.
I hope you realize what you're
getting yourself into.
I can't force the Bajora,
the Ferengi or anyone else
to send their children
to your school.
And even if they do come
everyone has a different culture
a different philosophy.
I know I'll have to come up
with an innovative program
but I can't imagine any parent
not welcoming the news
of a school opening here.
Thank you, Commander.
If I hear of you
hanging around with him...
I thought you didn't want
to talk about this now.
These are the DNA
sequence analyses
the cellular spectrographs
and the particulate
matter tracers.
I asked Lieutenant Dax
to confirm my findings
and I'm afraid she concurs.
There were no new DNA traces
found in the holosuite.
You're saying nobody went
into the room with him.
Well, apart from those of us
who were in there
after the body was discovered,
this was the only DNA present.
And we've identified
it as Ibudan's.
Wait a minute.
Ibudan goes
into the holosuite alone
locks the door.
Nobody transports in.
A few minutes later,
he's murdered.
How is that possible?
It's not...
unless the murder was committed
by someone who could get through
the cracks in the door.
Say... a shape-shifter.
It's a pretty neat package.
His calendar shows he was
planning to meet with me
at the time of the murder.
No one except a shape-shifter
could get into the holosuite.
And since I'd obviously
be called there
after the body was discovered
traces of my DNA wind up
at the scene of the crime.
Do you have
any kind of an alibi?
Major, I have to return
to my natural state
every 18 hours to regenerate.
To be quite honest about it
I was in a pail
in the back of my office
when Ibudan was killed.
The killer might have known
your regenerative cycle
and planned the murder
accordingly.
Like I said, a neat package.
Who might want
to frame you for murder?
I can think of
about 500 different people
but I haven't seen any of them
around the station recently.
Do you think
that Federation doctor
could do a sweep
of Ibudan's quarters for me?
See if he can find out
if somebody else was using
that second bed?
I'll send him
over there right away.
Thank you, Major.
Dabo!
You want my boy to go
to a Federation school?
Not just Federation.
I'm developing a curriculum
that will take
a much broader approach.
Little lady, little lady.
What do you know
of Ferengi education?
I understand you employ
a work-study approach, Mr. Rom
with apprenticeships
in a wide range
of business and economic fields.
We throw them
into the cutthroat competition
of Ferengi commerce
and anyone who survives,
graduates.
Are you prepared
to teach that to my son?
I'm sure I couldn't improve on
what you've already taught him
in that department.
Thank you.
I've taught him
everything I know.
It's so important
that we prepare our youths
for the challenges
of the future.
Exactly.
Consider the advantage
your son will have
over other Ferengi
once he's learned
about other cultures...
how others
run their economies
conduct business, negotiate...
You will teach my son
these things?
Knowledge is power, Mr. Rom.
It can't work.
He will not listen to you.
Why not?
You are female.
So?
My son cannot learn anything
from a female human teacher.
Let him try it for a few weeks.
He has nothing to lose
and so much to gain.
I don't think so.
Will you at least
think about it?
Yes, yes, of course.
Now, really, I'm quite busy.
Place your wagers,
place your wagers.
Get this lovely young woman
a drink.
What do we really
know about him anyway?
He's not one of us.
He isn't one of anything.
You know what
really bothers me?
This shifter was the
last Chief of Security
when the Cardassians
were here.
Yeah, he's the one
who caught Ibudan for them.
Why is he still Security Chief?
You're right.
We ought to talk to Major Kira.
Nobody knows him
like I know him.
Let me tell you something.
He's an ill-tempered,
overbearing crosspatch.
But he was
no Cardassian collaborator
and he's no killer.
I can't believe
you're defending him, Quark.
You're his worst enemy.
Guess that's the closest thing
he has in this world
to a friend.
Security, huh?
Listen, I hear
what you're saying.
I understand your concerns.
We're not saying whether
he's innocent or guilty,
Commander.
All we're saying...
Isn't it reasonable
under the circumstances...
Thank you very much for coming.
Oh, this is wrong.
And what would you
suggest we do?
He didn't do it.
The man we have in charge
of a murder investigation
is the prime suspect, Major.
Those people have
a right to complain.
Even if he's innocent
it could still seem like
a conflict of interest, Kira.
You're going to relieve him
of duty.
I don't see any other choice.
He has been completely candid
about this investigation.
He could have covered his tracks
half a dozen times already
if he were guilty.
I appreciate how you feel
but the decision stands.
I'll inform him myself.
The only curious thing I found
were these seofurance fragments
near the matter
reclamation unit.
Dish, please.
It appears he was trying
to get rid of them.
Do you have any idea
what they're from?
I know exactly
what they're from.
A biological sample container.
I use them all the time.
What would Ibudan be doing
with a biological
sample container?
Well, that I'm not so sure about
but when I analyzed
the fragments
I detected traces
of a complex organic structure.
Translate, Doctor.
It suggests Ibudan may
have been conducting
some sort of medical
experiment on board his ship.
He wasn't a doctor
or a scientist.
Well, let's see what a standard
electrophoretic analysis
tells us.
What the?
The complex proteins
are breaking down
into DNA fragments.
Now what does that mean?
It means...
we should set up
a bioregenerative field
to accelerate
the cellular development.
If I can reconstruct
the DNA sequence
it might just give us
an idea what he was up to.
Sisko to Odo.
Here.
May I see you in my office,
please?
Acknowledged.
Commander?
Sit down.
I am temporarily
relieving you of duty.
I'm sure the reasons
are obvious.
Who will be taking over
the investigation?
I've placed Major Kira
and Lieutenant Dax in charge.
Will that be all, Commander?
I want you to know
I don't personally believe
that you're responsible
for this.
Really?
Now, how can that be true?
You don't know me.
You have no reason to believe
I wouldn't kill Ibudan
if it suited my fancy.
So don't tell me there isn't
some doubt inside of you...
some question
about whether or not
I murdered the man.
I simply feel
that putting Kira and Dax
in charge of the investigation
will be in everyone's
best interest
including your own.
I'll take care
of my own best interests.
That's him.
Yeah, they found his DNA...
I can find out
who did it for you.
Not for me.
Tell it to Starfleet.
I'm not in charge
here any longer.
Well now, there's a piece
of good news to brighten my day.
You better take advantage
of my absence while
you can, Quark.
Oh, I will, I will.
Count on it.
I'll have every
confidence man in the sector
on board by tomorrow.
You do and I'll...
What?
You're going to get sloppy
without me to keep
an eye on you.
I don't think so.
You've kept me on my toes
for far too long now.
Sure.
I've turned you
into a better crook.
Like it or not.
Quark, think you could use
a shape-shifter
in your organization?
Uh...
You had me going.
I did, didn't I?
Yes, you did.
You know, I've been
asking some friends
at Kran-Tobal Prison
about lbudan...
whether he made any enemies
while he was there.
Couldn't find any.
Mostly he stayed around
the Bajoran dissidents
that the Cardassians locked up.
It's growing exponentially.
We're going to have to increase
the metabolic field energy.
Just what is it
that's growing in there?
Aren't those DNA patterns
humanoid, Julian?
Well, that's what
it looks like to me
but there's a genetic drift
I can't quite put my finger on.
What was Ibudan up to?
We're going to have
to wait and see
what this becomes
before we have a clue.
You can transfer it
to the larger field now.
Yes, Doctor.
Care for lunch?
Sure.
No, thank you.
Major Kira's waiting
for my report.
Just how many different lives
do you think she's led?
I don't even know.
He'll go... she'll go
through a list of them
then out comes another one
in a later conversation.
I'd guess that Jadzia
is probably the sixth host.
Has she changed much?
Changed?
From the last one, Curzon Dax?
I understand a Trill
integrates the personality
of each new host.
I guess I'll have
to find that out.
If I were to tell you
some of the mischief
he and I used to get into...
There was a time when
I was no older than you are
we were attending the running
of the Rujian Steeplechase.
Dax loves the races.
Anyway, there were
these gorgeous, seven-foot
Ruji twin sisters
that Curzon knew.
And he and I...
I guess we won't be doing that
again soon, will we?
You care for her
a great deal, don't you?
Dax and I
are just friends, Doctor.
If you're interested
you have nothing to fear
from me.
I mean,
if I were in your shoes
knowing Dax
as intimately as you do
I think I'd find her
hard to resist.
You don't understand, Doctor.
Dax used to beat me
regularly at bare fist
Juro Counterpunch.
Well, I guess you won't be doing
that again soon either.
Let's get out of here.
No, I'm not drinking
with scum.
I won't drink near this man.
Come on, let's go.
Yeah, in a semicircle here
facing the module.
That's right.
Thank you.
Ah.
Here's Mommy.
Where have you been, Mommy?
I've been getting ready
for school tomorrow, honey.
Can I come to school?
Oh, I wish you could.
At least then I'd know
one student would be coming.
But you have
to wait a year or two.
How's it going?
We'll be ready in time.
In time for what, I'm not sure.
Aside from Commander Sisko
we haven't had
a firm commitment
from any of the parents.
What's this?
Just a little something
I replicated
on the way over.
Help Mommy to open
her present, Molly.
Come on.
Yeah, go on.
Pull.
Oh, Miles.
Thank you.
I want to see you standing
in the Promenade
tomorrow morning
ringing your school bell.
Murderer!
I better take her home.
Killer!
Don't you know
you're not wanted?
There he is. Get him.
You don't belong...
Murderer!
Shape-shifting freak!
O'Brien to Ops.
Security to the Promenade,
on the double.
Acknowledged.
Yes, sir.
O'Brien to Sisko.
I'm here, Chief.
What's going on?
We've got a crowd...
more like a mob...
outside Odo's office.
You better get down here.
Freak!
Shape-shifter!
Murdering shifter!
Odo's inside?
Yes, sir. He went in
a few minutes ago.
The crowd followed him
from the bar.
I want more security here,
and I want them armed.
Aye, sir.
It's going to be harder
to control them
if the numbers keep growing.
We can secure all turbolifts...
slow down the traffic
onto the Promenade.
Good idea.
Julian, look at this.
The chromatin pattern's
changing.
It's definitely humanoid.
It's definitely
humanoid.
It's definitely...
My God!
Dax, I think I know what it is.
Run a chromosome analysis.
I think we're going to find
a gene-sequence degradation.
Shifter! Shifter!
Shifter!
Shifter! Shifter! Shifter!
Coming through.
What the hell do you people
intend to accomplish here?
We want the shape-shifter.
And what do you think
you're going to do to him
if you get to him?
He deserves to die.
'Bout time!
He's right!
How do you get a rope
around the neck
of a shape-shifter?
Listen to me.
You will disperse immediately.
Return to your quarters.
Return to your ships.
He's a murderer.
We want justice.
Do you?
Justice?
Really?
Is it justice you're after
or just some way to express
your anger, your fear?
Look at yourselves.
In an hour, you'll regret
what you tried to do here.
Do not condemn this man
because he is different
than you are.
We condemn him because
of the evidence.
Yeah!
Then take that evidence
to a court of law.
There will be no justice
served here today.
Commander!
Commander Sisko,
I believe we have
some new evidence to consider.
The man who was murdered
was not Ibudan.
What?!
Come with me.
All right, break it up now.
Move on, people.
Let's clear the area.
You heard what she said.
Let's go.
Come on.
Back to your quarters.
Quickly. Move!
A clone.
That's what Ibudan
was working on.
Creating a clone of himself.
And then he killed the clone
to frame me for his murder.
How can we be sure
the victim was a clone?
A clone has identical DNA
to that of the donor
but certain cloning
methods cause
a characteristic
gene-sequence degradation
which can be detected.
If you know to look for it.
We've matched
the victim's gene sequence
with the fellow in the jar here.
They're definitely both clones.
And what happens to this one?
In about two days
he becomes a living,
breathing member
of Bajoran society.
Let's hope he doesn't follow
in his donor's footsteps.
What about Ibudan?
I have an idea
where to find him.
Computer, lights.
Who are you?
How did you get in here?
Oh, I think you know.
I warn you,
I'll call Ship Security.
Do that.
I have some interesting
questions to ask them.
For example, I'm especially
curious to know
how the name Lamonay S.
Came to appear on this ship's
passenger list yesterday.
That is my name
and I arranged transport
on this vessel.
Why should that be so strange?
You did not arrive on this ship.
No.
Well, just what ship did you
arrive on, Mr. Lamonay S?
I can't find any record
of your arrival
on any vessel that has docked
here in the last three weeks.
I assure you, you are in error.
In fact, I think you
did arrive on this ship
and that you spent
the last few years
in a prison among
Bajoran dissidents.
One of whom I've
learned was a scientist
who was arrested
by the Cardassians
for conducting
experimental research
into tri-phasic cloning.
Killing your own clone
is still murder.
Commander's Log,
Stardate 46421.5.
Ibudan has been turned over
to the Bajoran authorities
just hours after his clone
gained consciousness
and began a new life.
The perpetrators
of the mob violence
have retreated
into their own business.
To my knowledge,
Odo has received no apologies.
Meanwhile, life on the station
has begun to return to normal.
Computer, what time is it?
0907 hours.
I guess you were right.
It isn't going to be easy.
Maybe it's just going
to take a little time...
Sit down!
Not next to that human boy.
I don't want you to have
anything to do with him.
We'll... try it
for a few weeks.
Please come in.
Uh, take any seat.
Try to be on time from now on.
My name is Keiko O'Brien.
I'll be your teacher.
Why don't we turn
on our computers
and access the files on Bajor
to find out a little bit more
about the people and
history of this world.