[muffled shouting]
Look, save your energy.
We'll have you out of there
as soon as possible.
I hope.
Try rerouting
the power coupling.
Mr. O'Brien.
See if you can activate
the interlock servos.
Mr. O'Brien.
Captain Jaheel, those people
have been stuck in that air lock
for over an hour.
Now, if you can wait
till we get that door opened
I'll be happy to listen
to any problems you might have.
But I've already been waiting two days
for your people to readjust
my ship's antimatter flow converter.
I'm afraid we've gotten a little behind
in our maintenance schedule.
I'm not interested in hearing excuses.
I have a shipment of Tamen Sahsheer
waiting to be delivered to Largo V,
and I'll need to do better than warp 1
to get there before it spoils.
I'll try to get a repair crew
to you by the end of the day.
Now, that's the best I can do.
Your best, Mr. O'Brien,
hardly seems good enough.
[woman] Dax to O'Brien.
O'Brien here.
Can you spare a minute, Chief?
I have a little problem here at the lab.
On my way.
Thanks for coming, Chief.
What are you doing out here?
[loud whining]
Have you checked the EPS converter?
Yes, first thing.
-How about the intensity grid?
-It's fine.
Then it's probably the secondary
phase modulator.
We had trouble with them last week
in the main power core.
That should do it.
[noise stops]
Anything else I can do for you?
The navigational computer
hasn't worked reliably for three days.
I ask for the star charts
for the Argosian sector--
Glessene sector
comes up instead.
That's when I can coax
this system on line.
[O'Brien] Uh-huh.
Try it now.
Huh! That's more like it.
You look like you
could use some sleep.
Who has time for sleep?
I'd settle for five minutes
peace and quiet.
Chief, I thought you were going
to fix the replicators.
You're absolutely right, sir.
I knew I'd forgotten something.
Can't have the Operations Chief
sitting around daydreaming
when there's work
to be done, can we?
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
I'll get right on it.
"Fix the replicators, Chief."
"My console's off-line, Chief."
[groaning]
I should have transferred
to a cargo drone--
no people, no complaints.
[sighs]
[instrument humming]
Hot coffee-- black, double sweet.
[beeping]
[Odo] Tell me, Quark.
Am I mistaken, or is business
a little slow today?
Slow? It's been almost nonexistent
for the past three days.
Mmm. Who knows?
If things don't improve
you may be forced to close down.
Oh, you'd like that, wouldn't you?
Well, let's just say, without you around
my job would be considerably easier.
Without me around,
you'd be forced to find
some other poor innocent to persecute.
Think about that while you sit here
gloating at my misfortune.
Quark!
You call this Kohlian stew?
If your meal isn't satisfactory
I'm sure we could, uh, exchange it
for something more to your liking.
Aren't you the least bit curious
as to how it tastes?
[groaning]
Now...
you served it.
You're going to eat it.
All right, that's enough.
I said, eat it!
I said...
that's enough.
Leave him alone.
Well, another satisfied customer.
It's these replicators.
If I don't get them fixed soon,
they'll destroy my business.
Why not get O'Brien to fix them?
He has the replicators on
the command level working perfectly.
I'm on his waiting list.
He assures me he'll get to them
as soon as he can.
Mmm...
No telling when that will be.
The Chief's a very busy man.
Computer...
display a station layout.
Highlight locations
of all repaired replicators
on command level.
[female voice on machine]
Information restricted
to security clearance 5 and above.
Please enter security verification.
Clearance verified.
There you go, sir.
I think you'll find that
more to your liking.
Very much appreciated, Mr. O'Brien.
Don't mention it, sir.
Unfortunately,
there are plenty of replicators
around the station
that still need looking after.
You all right, Chief?
I'm just a bit hot.
The environmental controls
must be acting up again.
Send my regards to Mrs. O'Brien.
Jake tells me she's a wonderful teacher.
Oh, that's nice to hear, sir.
She's flower units about the lad herself.
Excuse me?
Sir?
What was that you just said?
She's... quite fond of the lad herself.
Oh.
I'm glad to hear it.
Very good, sir.
[man] Ladies.
Hello, Lieutenant.
Oh, I forgot how different it was.
How different what was?
Being female.
I haven't been one for over 80 years.
All this attention.
Imagine it must take
some getting used to.
Actually, I find it quite enjoyable.
Major Kira.
Lieutenant Dax.
I'd be honored to have you
join my little party--
as my guests, of course.
What's all this, Quark?
You cheat your 1,000th customer?
Who says Bajorans
don't have a sense of humor?
Actually, uh, we're celebrating the repair
of the bar's replicator system.
Perhaps I could interest you
in a nice, double-whipped,
I'danian spice pudding.
Oh, what do you think?
I think I'm due back at Ops
but, uh, go on.
Enjoy yourself.
Chief?
[slurring] How can I help you, Major?
Looks like you're the one
who could use a little help.
Oh, no, I'm fine, really.
I suppose this isn't
a good time to tell you
that number three turbolift
has broken down again.
Joking, Chief.
Major, lark's true pepper.
What?
Let birds go further loose maybe.
Shout easy play.
Chief, you're not making any sense.
Round the turbulent quick.
Well, close the reverse harbor.
A-Ankle try sound.
Reset gleaming.
D-Dinner to bug.
Chief, wait.
When?
Chief.
Computer, continue neural imaging scan
and stimulate visual cortex.
[female automated voice]
All visual responses normal.
Begin auditory stimuli.
[woman] No physiological damage.
All brain functions
within normal parameters.
-Nurse.
-Yes?
Will you pull up Mr. O'Brien's
neurophysiological history, please?
Yes, Doctor.
What is that? What's he written?
I wish I knew.
Strike limits flame the dark true salt.
Please, Chief, take a seat.
Way link complete.
Way link!
What's wrong with him?
He appears to suffering
from a form of aphasia.
It's a perceptual dysfunction
in which aural and visual stimuli
are incorrectly processed by the brain.
His actual thinking hasn't been affected
but he's incapable of expressing himself
or understanding others.
Victory strike limits frosted wake.
Simple hesitation!
I'm not sure I follow you, Doctor.
You say Mr. O'Brien is aphasiac
but all of his tests
have come up negative.
Isn't aphasia typically associated
with some kind of cranial trauma?
Yes. It can occur as a result of a stroke
or a blow to the head.
But there's no evidence of that here.
Did you check the medical library
for any precedents?
And rechecked-- nothing, so far.
You have any theories?
Not yet.
Find one.
Major Kira, get a hold
of the Chief's personal duty log.
I want to know where he's been
and what he's done for the past 52 hours.
I've already examined it, Commander.
He's been all over this station.
Retrace his steps and see what
you come up with.
Dax, you will temporarily assume
Mr. O'Brien's duties.
Yes, uh... Um...
Is there a problem, Lieutenant?
Lieutenant?
I'm sorry, Benjamin.
I'm unable to...
foolish assembled regal...
control weather.
Spontaneous development of aphasia
is virtually impossible.
Yet we saw Lieutenant Dax
become aphasiac before our eyes.
This told me we were
dealing with a disease
which only mimics aphasia,
so I ran a full neural synaptic comparison
between Dax and O'Brien
and I found this in the temporal lobes
of both patients.
A virus.
It imposes itself
within the established synaptic pathways
and then randomly reroutes them.
For example, when I look at this,
a process occurs within my brain
which connects the stimulus
to the word "tricorder."
This virus disrupts that process.
I'd see a tricorder
but I'd say something ridiculous,
like "window."
Exactly.
Doctor, I think you should get over here.
-Night the flow trade again.
-You lost pile luck.
Away tunnel back the garden.
Doctor, I want this station
put under emergency quarantine
immediately.
Yes, sir.
[conversation and music]
[man] Dabo!
[shouting]
Quark, what is going on here?
What does it look like?
It looks like business as usual
but that's impossible
because all shops and businesses
have been closed until further notice.
Except, of course,
for essential station operations.
For which this place hardly qualifies.
I don't think they'd agree.
This quarantine has everybody
on edge, Constable.
Would you deprive them
of a little harmless diversion?
They'd be safer in their quarters.
Quark, this Kohlian stew-- magnificent.
Fortunately, my assistant, Rom,
was able to fix the replicators.
Yes... Very fortunate.
[Sisko] Jake...
I expected you home an hour ago.
Sorry. I was at Nog's.
Dad, about this quarantine--
it's going to be OK, isn't it?
It's just a precaution, nothing more.
[Jaheel] I wish I shared your
confidence, Commander.
Go straight home, son.
I'll see you at dinner.
Captain Jaheel, all visitors
have been confined to their ships.
Believe me,
there is no place I'd rather be.
Then what are you doing here?
Commander, I officially request permission
to leave this station.
Request denied.
But none of my crew
has been affected by this virus of yours.
And unless I depart at once
my whole cargo will be ruined!
Captain, I suggest
you return to your ship now.
Please. I don't want to get sick.
I'm sorry, but until we can
find a cure for this... thing,
no one's going anywhere.
Computer,
let's start with one
Ferengi Starduster, please.
Extra strong.
Perfect.
Uh... I thought the front wheels
were sticking a bit.
Unauthorized access
to crew quarters is a crime, Quark.
You could have just asked
to use the replicators.
There's an old Ferengi saying--
"Never ask when you can take."
Uh, how did you figure it out?
You claimed Rom fixed your replicators.
-So?
-Rom's an idiot.
He couldn't fix a straw if it was bent.
You're right. Rom is an idiot.
Remind me to get rid of him tomorrow.
Based on the levels of the virus
found in the patients' blood,
I believe it's being
absorbed through ingestion.
-You're saying it's in our food?
-Well, that's not possible.
All the food on this station is replicated
and all the replicators use biofilters.
They automatically screen out contaminants
including viruses.
Major, I've analyzed samples
from replicators all over the station.
Food on the command level is contaminated.
But all of us here have
eaten from those replicators.
How come we're not aphasic?
This virus is highly adaptable.
Its incubation period
seems to vary within each individual.
According to O'Brien's duty log
the last thing he did
before becoming aphasic
was fix the command level replicators.
Get a repair crew over there
to inspect the site.
Let's shut down those replicators.
Maybe we'll be able
to limit further contamination.
I'm afraid that's not going to do it, sir.
I've been getting aphasic patients
from all over the station.
How is that possible?
You can thank Quark.
I caught him using a replicator
in one of the vacant crew quarters.
He was producing
his entire menu out of there.
If this virus is present
within a large enough segment
of the population
it could mean...
What is it, Doctor?
I just took an air sample.
[Sisko] The virus...
It's mutated into an airborne variety.
Which means?
Which means the whole station is infected.
[Sisko] Station Log, Stardate 46423.7.
Nearly 60% of DS9's population
has now contracted the aphasia virus.
We've initiated standard
quarantine procedures
and are advising all incoming ships
to maintain their distance
from the station
until further notice.
I found it in the replicator's
pattern generator.
O'Brien must have accidentally
triggered it when he repaired the system.
According to Bashir, it introduced
an anomalous programming sequence
into the materialization subroutine.
In effect, it built the virus
directly into the replicated food
at a molecular level.
-So what we have here is sabotage.
-Cardassian sabotage.
-How can you be sure?
-Has a diboridium core for a power source.
That is Cardassian technology.
[man] Bashir to Sisko.
Sisko here.
[man] Commander, I think you'd better
get down here to the infirmary
as soon as possible.
On my way.
You wanted to see me, Doctor?
Jake?
Left... become better...
control... entire hope.
[Bashir] We've converted
some empty crew quarters
into a hospital ward.
He'll be well looked after.
I'll take him there myself.
Come on, Jake.
You're going to be all right.
Commander, when you've got a moment,
I've found something I'd like to show you.
[people muttering]
[woman] It'll be all right.
Just lay back.
[coughing]
[woman] I know,
but just lay back and relax.
[Quark] Food... dabo... drinks...
money... hand... mine... give!
Well, Quark, I see even you couldn't
weasel your way clear of this one.
You underestimate the Ferengi
immune system, Commander.
I'm merely here visiting
my less fortunate customers
to make sure they're
not faking the illness
to avoid paying their bills.
No one could be that devious.
I am.
You... gold... owe... me!
[indistinct conversation]
[Quark] I... now... give...
Up!
We're doing everything possible.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
The virus is synthetic, Commander.
Its nucleotide sequence is too perfect.
It's clearly not natural.
You're saying the Cardassians
genetically engineered this thing?
Well, that's what I thought at first,
but I've studied Cardassian
genetic engineering.
They always build distinctive
monoclonial links into their DNA.
This virus has none of those features.
All right, then who made it?
Well, that's what I wanted to find out.
So I referenced all known
DNA construction techniques
in the Federation records
and this protein series was the key.
It indicates--
Doctor! Who created this virus?
The Bajorans, sir.
I believe it must have been
a terrorist plot
to sabotage the Cardassians
while they were here.
The energy decay of the power core
indicates it dates back
to the building of the station.
[Odo] That's 18 years ago.
I suppose the Bajoran underground
could have smuggled it aboard
during construction...
before I took over as Head of Security.
But why would the underground
go to all the trouble
of planting a booby trap
and not set it off?
Maybe they forgot.
No. More likely, they were captured
or killed before they could release it.
We need to find out
who created this virus.
You're our best hope.
[sighing] 18 years is a long time.
Besides, even if she finds who did this,
that's no guarantee they can help us.
We just have to hope
they remember the antidote.
That's assuming they ever
bothered to create one.
It had to be someone
in the underground
familiar with genetic engineering.
[Galis] Eighteen years ago?
Sounds like something Dekon Elig
might have thought up.
How can I find him?
The last I heard
he was in a Cardassian prison.
Where was he being held?
The Velos VII Internment Camp,
but that was nine years ago.
And you have no idea where he is now?
Think, Galis! This is important.
I'm sorry, Kira,
but it was all so long ago.
What is it, Jake?
Roll linger when life.
Roll linger when...
What?
Other support, strong courage...
[gasps]
He's running a high fever.
Open way long.
Open way.
Doctor, we have an emergency
in crew quarters.
How is he, Doctor?
Not good, I'm afraid.
The virus has attacked
his autonomic nervous system.
Can he be stabilized?
He hasn't responded to neural stimulation.
I've given him 30cc's of corophizine
to avoid secondary infection,
but so far, I've been unable
to lower his fever.
What are his chances?
Unless I find some way
to counteract the virus,
he'll be dead in 12 hours.
Have you made any progress?
No.
I've tried base pair destabilizers,
sequential disruption--
nothing seems to affect it.
Sir, I've got seven other aphasic patients
displaying the same symptoms
as O'Brien here,
and I'm afraid this is only the beginning.
Keep searching, Doctor.
I hope Major Kira finds whoever's
responsible for creating this virus.
I'd like to meet that person myself.
This virus is a work of genius.
I'll try to arrange it for you.
[womanr] Link established with
the Bajoran Archival Records.
Locate files on Velos VII Internment Camp.
[female voice on computer]
Ready.
Do you show a record
of an inmate named Dekon Elig?
Affirmative.
Biographical data.
Dekon Elig, geneticist.
Former member of the Higa Metar sect
of the Bajoran underground.
Killed while attempting escape,
Stardate 39355.
Certificate of Death on file.
No need to ask how you're doing.
Chasing after ghosts.
You have 12 hours to catch one.
And then?
People start dying.
Computer...
display Dekon Elig's Certificate of Death.
Identify signature of witness.
[woman] Certificate of Death
was witnessed by Surmak Ren,
Bajoran medical assistant.
Show me biographical data on Surmak Ren.
Dr. Surmak Ren.
Former member of the Higa Metar sect
of the Bajoran underground.
Repatriated to Bajor upon closing
of the Velos VII Internment Camp,
Stardate 46302.
Current status unknown.
[clicking whir]
[clicking slows]
[clicking stops]
Dabo.
Any luck?
I haven't won a spin in hours.
Uh, care to place a friendly wager?
If it's your reputation
you're thinking about,
no one need ever know.
It has nothing to do with my reputation.
[sighs]
The truth is, I never...
learned the game.
You mean, you've sat here
for all these years
and you don't even know how to gamble?
That's correct.
No wonder you always look so bored.
The rules are quite simple, actually.
I'd be happy to show them to you.
Some other time, perhaps.
Sisko needs me in Ops.
And, since the entire security force
has been stricken with aphasia
the Promenade is in
a very vulnerable position.
How unfortunate.
Consider it a warning, Quark.
Because I'm holding you
personally responsible
if anything turns up missing.
Is that understood?
Perfectly.
Hmm.
Dabo.
Computer, analyze test sample 37 delta.
Detail effects on viral containment.
[female voice on computer] Working.
Analysis complete.
Sample 37 delta ineffective.
Viral protein sheath is unaffected.
Nucleotide sequence remains intact.
Computer, replay morning.
[female voice on computer]
Command unclear. Please repeat.
Glass lunch judge a bin to let it.
[female voice on computer]
Command unclear. Please repeat.
Computer, establish a link
with the Bajoran Medical Index
for the, uh, Northwestern District.
[female voice on computer]
Link established.
Access all information on Dr. Surmak Ren.
[female voice on computer]
There are no records matching that name.
Try the Northeastern District--
same search.
[female voice on computer]
Dr. Surmak Ren, currently serving
as Chief Administrator
of the Ilvian Medical Complex.
Computer, open a channel
to the Ilvian Medical Complex
Administrator's office.
This is Dr. Surmak. And you are?
Major Kira Nerys,
Bajoran liaison to Deep Space 9.
Ah, yes, the old Cardassian
mining station.
How can I help you?
It depends.
On what?
On whether or not you helped Dekon Elig
plant an aphasia virus here 18 years ago.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Look, Sisko, I'm a security officer--
a good one--
but that doesn't make me qualified
to help you run station operations.
You're probably right, Constable.
But, as you can see,
you're all I've got.
[Kira] Commander...
Commander, I think I found our scientist.
-Does he have an antidote?
-I don't know.
He broke the connection
the minute I mentioned the virus.
Major, you mind telling me
where you're going?
To continue my conversation
with Dr. Surmak, in person.
Major, I can't allow you
to break quarantine.
We can't risk
spreading the virus to Bajor.
I am well aware of that, Commander.
As a matter of fact,
I don't intend to step foot on the planet.
Better let her go, Sisko.
She's all we've got.
Let's just hope there's someone left
to greet her when she returns.
Jake.
How's it going?
I've missed you.
I know things don't look
too good right now,
but they'll get better.
You have to believe that...
because I'm not going
to lose you, Jake.
You hear me?
I'm not going to lose you.
You better take a look at this.
We have activity on Docking Port 5.
I think a ship is about to depart.
Docking Port 5? That's Jaheel's ship.
Put him on screen.
Captain, your ship has
not been cleared for departure.
The mooring clamps are locked,
and I don't intend to release them.
I suggest you change your mind.
I'm taking aft thrusters to one half.
Captain, cut your engines
before you rip your ship apart.
He's not reducing power.
Jaheel, I'm ordering you to stand down.
Your orders are no concern of mine.
My entire crew has been
confined to your hospital.
I must leave now
while I can still function.
Look, I understand that you're frightened
but believe me, you're better off here.
You don't want to be out there alone
and get hit by the virus.
Don't worry about me, I'm fine.
And I plan to stay that way.
-And if you think you're go--
-[cuts transmission]
We'll have to retract the clamps.
Once he's clear of the station
we can grab him with a tractor beam.
-Damn.
-What's wrong?
There's too much stress
on the mooring clamps.
They're not retracting.
[groaning]
[console beeping]
His aft isolation plate buckled.
His main power core's been ruptured.
If the internal fuel cells collapse,
the whole ship will explode.
And take half the docking ring with it.
Computer, isolate a com line
to the Ilvian Medical Complex
Administrator's office.
[female voice on computer] Line isolated.
Scan office for life-forms.
One life-form present.
Lock on and stand by to transport.
-This is Dr. Surmak.
-Hello again, Doctor.
Just checking to see
you're in your office.
I have nothing to say to you--
Hello again, Doctor.
This is outrageous.
I demand you return me
to my office immediately.
Relax, Doctor. You won't be gone long.
Try to reestablish visual contact
with Jaheel's ship.
[Odo] No response. His com lines are down.
Bypass communications
through a secondary grid.
See if you can switch
to external pickups.
Got it.
His fire control systems
don't appear to be working.
We have about 15 minutes
before the fuel cells collapse.
I hope you feel better than you look.
Must be that damn virus.
This is Sisko.
Any station personnel who can understand
what I'm saying, come to Ops immediately.
We need help up here.
We have to get that ship
away from the station.
Why don't we explode
the mooring clamps?
The blast should push the ship
away from the docking ring.
We'll have to get down there
and blow it manually.
[groans]
I'll do it.
All right.
You can cross barrels.
All job appalled.
What was that?
Bread...
the arrive...
seen earlier.
Oh, I see.
Major, this is kidnapping.
Turn this ship around
or I swear you will spend
the rest of your life
in Kran-Tobol Prison.
Fine. But first, we need your help.
The aphasia virus is spreading
through the station.
Why come to me?
You helped create the virus, didn't you?
No, I had practically
nothing to do with it.
Dekon Elig created the virus.
I was merely his medical assistant.
That seems like a lifetime ago now.
I was only in the underground
for six months
before we were captured.
I am not responsible for this.
I am not looking to place blame!
All I want is the antidote.
I don't know of any antidote.
If Dekon created one, he never told me.
Listen, Surmak.
I have a station full of dying people
and you are the closest thing there is
to an expert on this virus.
I sympathize, Major,
but I don't think I can help you.
All right.
Then how about helping yourself?
Meaning what?
Meaning...
I've been infected
with your virus, Doctor...
so now you're infected, too.
To anyone who can hear me, this is Odo.
Sisko's infected.
I could really use some help here in Ops.
Do I detect a note of panic in your voice?
Quark.
Am I to believe that you're
volunteering to help?
Who said anything about volunteering?
We can haggle over price later.
Now, um...
how may I be of use?
I need to get to Docking Port 5 now.
That ship's going to explode
in five minutes.
I'll beam you over.
-You?
-Relax.
I served on a Ferengi freighter
for eight years.
All right.
I must have witnessed the procedure
hundreds of times.
Witnessed? You mean to say you never
handled the controls yourself?
Energizing!
[sighing]
Kira to Ops. Approaching Landing Pad 7.
Request clearance
to initiate docking procedure.
[Quark] Welcome back.
I could use some help up here.
Quark, what are you doing in Ops?
[laughing]
First thing I need to see
is your doctor's viral
characterization research.
He was beginning to develop
an antidote series.
Let's take a look at that.
[Kira] Listen, Doctor, um...
I'll be in Ops.
If you need me, use this string impact.
Lot show red intense.
I think you'd better sit down, Major.
[alarm wailing]
[Jaheel] Dog fellow distance.
[Odo] Yeah, tell me about it.
[Quark] Odo, you'd better hurry up.
That ship's going to explode
in one minute.
Virum protein sheath.
Nucleotide sequence.
Yes.
That's right.
It's an adaptive, synaptic inhibitor.
Dekon was brilliant.
No doubt of that.
I think we've found your antidote, Major.
[Quark] 40 seconds.
30 seconds. Hurry!
I know, I know.
20 seconds!
Ten seconds!
[alarm blares]
[gasps]
[Quark] Odo? Quark to Odo.
You still with us?
Try not to sound too disappointed.
Now, about that little matter
of my hazard pay...
Why, you...
Come on. Come on.
[Sisko] Station Log, Stardate 46425.8.
With the help of Dr. Bashir's notes,
Dr. Surmak was able to find
an antidote for the aphasia virus.
We are continuing to administer
it throughout the station
and things are slowly
returning to normal.
Good to have you back, Chief.
Thank you, sir.
Coffee, black.
O'Brien!