So, there I was...
fighting the toughest battle
of my life...
looking around,
hoping to spot a friendly face
only to discover
my colleagues...
were gone.
I was alone.
I admit for a moment there
I considered giving up.
I could feel
the seconds ticking away--
panic building up
inside of me.
I knew my only chance
was to trust my instincts,
so I closed my eyes...
took a deep breath,
and just like that,
it came to me--
the answer I was looking for--
a pericardial membrane!
Oh!
I looked down
and punched the answer
into my computer terminal
just as the buzzer sounded,
ending the exam,
and that, I suppose
is the stuff
salutatorians are made of.
Salutatorian?
Well, I mistook
a preganglionic fiber
for a postganglionic nerve
during the orals,
or I would have been
valedictorian.
It was a trick question.
Fascinating.
Not nearly as fascinating
as when I...
SISKO:
Dr. Bashir, Chief O'Brien.
Report to Landing Pad Five.
Bad timing.
There'll be another time.
Starfleet medical finals.
Gets them every time.
( grunting )
It's no use.
Chief!
We have to get
this hatch open.
Lieutenant Dax and Ensign Pauley
are trapped in there.
The runabout barely made it back
through the wormhole.
By the time they docked
power levels were near zero.
There's not even enough juice
left in the ship
to release the servos.
Life support's down.
Oxygen levels have dropped
dangerously low.
Have to burn it through.
Forget it, major.
The hatch is made
of duranium composite.
It'll take you an hour
to get through it.
We don't have that much time.
That's odd.
How many passengers did you say
were on board the Ganges?
Two.
I'm reading three.
O'BRIEN:
We need to get power
to the hatch servos.
Major, hand me
the EPI capacitor.
There, middle shelf.
( powering up )
( beeping )
Try her now.
( grunting )
Dax?
I'm fine.
Check the others.
Vash?
That's right.
Miles O'Brien,
from the Enterprise.
Oh. Yes, of course.
What are you doing
on the Ganges?
We found her
in the Gamma Quadrant.
She'd been there
for over two years.
Two years?
Doctor, we'd better
get these people
over to the infirmary.
Right this way.
O'BRIEN:
How did you get to the Gamma
Quadrant two years ago?
A friend
dropped me off.
Oh.
Will I live?
You're fine.
In fact...
you're in
remarkable shape.
Thank you, doctor.
I try.
Well, I-I-I-I mean
you've, uh...
managed quite well
considering you've
been out of contact
with civilization
for over two years.
Well, I'd hardly call
the Gamma Quadrant uncivilized.
Some of the cultures
I've encountered
have histories dating back
millions of years.
Really? I'd love
to hear about them.
I mean, we have no idea
what's beyond the wormhole.
Well, maybe I'll write a book.
Well, it's sure to be a
best-seller around here.
I... well... um...
no sign of disease
or malnutrition
or parasitic infections.
You sound disappointed.
I am.
Now I have no reason
to keep you here.
Well, you almost make me wish
I wasn't feeling well.
( sighing )
And she claims she knew nothing
about the wormhole?
She did seem very surprised
when I told her about it.
I don't think she ever expected
to see this part
of the galaxy again.
How could she get there
in the first place
if she didn't go
through the wormhole?
She said she didn't
want to talk about it.
Said it was
a personal matter.
This doesn't make sense--
a human alone in the Gamma
Quadrant for two years.
Let's check her background.
See what we can
find out about her.
She claims to be
an archaeologist.
That's a good
place to start.
You sure this place is safe?
The Assay Office
is the most secure
area on the station.
The chambers are
surrounded on all sides
by individual
force fields.
And how are
the locks controlled?
Once you secure a chamber,
it can't be opened,
except with your personal
authorization code,
combined with a verified
retinal print.
A Cardassian MK-7 scanner?
MK-12.
With an L-90
enhanced resolution filter.
Well, I suppose
that will have to do.
Computer, begin inventory
for cubicle 19.
One statue...
stone.
30-odd centimeters tall,
approximately eight kilograms.
Assorted gems.
Gold necklace.
One dagger...
bronze and gold.
About 25 centimeters.
ASSAYER:
Beautiful.
I've never seen anything
quite like it.
Some kind of Promethean quartz.
I thought so, too, at first,
but its molecular density
and refraction index
is much higher.
Remarkable.
End inventory.
Please,
enter an access code.
( beeping )
( cubicle closes )
All right.
I'll be back tomorrow
to pick everything up.
I've booked passage
on the Mulzirak Transport.
You're not leaving us
so soon, are you?
I'm afraid so.
The Daystrom Institute
will be very disappointed.
The Daystrom Institute?
Their scientists
are anxious
to hear about life
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Every place you've been,
everything you've seen,
no matter
how insignificant,
could prove to be important,
including how you got there.
Sorry, Commander,
but that's a...
Personal matter.
...personal matter.
So now the Daystrom
Institute is
interested in me.
Well, that's ironic.
Professor Woo
seemed especially eager
to speak to you again.
Did he really?
I suppose he told you
he suspended my membership
from the Institute's
Archaeological Council?
On two occasions.
Something about the sale
of illegal artifacts.
Well, when it
comes to choosing
between science
and profit
I'll choose profit
every time.
The professor was hoping you'd
make an exception in this case.
You know, I haven't
been back to Earth in...
it must be 12 years.
Here's your chance.
I could arrange passage.
I think I'd like that.
Fine. I'll take care of it.
I don't understand it,
Commander.
I can't find anything
wrong with her.
This ship is
completely functional.
It didn't look that way
this morning.
Oh, don't get me wrong.
The power reserves are empty.
The inertial damping fields
are barely operational,
and the warp drive
containment field's
on the verge of collapse.
But?
But there's nothing
wrong with any of them.
Once we put power
back into her,
she should be
fully operational.
Did you check the central
power linkages?
Yes, sir.
I ran a level-1 diagnostic.
Everything checks out.
I can't explain it.
It's like something
tapped into the ship's systems
and drained them dry.
Tell me, Chief, how well
do you know this woman Vash?
Hardly at all.
Only met her
that one time
she was aboard
the Enterprise.
What was she doing there?
Well, sir, Vash
and Captain Picard
were friends--
close friends,
if you follow my meaning.
Seems they met on Risa
a few years back.
I figure she must be
a special woman,
being friends with
the captain and all.
Somehow, she doesn't seem
to be his type.
Well, the captain likes
a good challenge, sir.
( equipment powering down )
Status report?
We suffered
a broad-spectrum power drain.
Power transfer is
completely inoperative.
The energy was drawn out
faster than it could handle.
I'll have to replace
the whole unit.
Chief, are you reading
any graviton flux
around the transfer systems?
I am detecting a low-level
graviton disturbance.
How did you know?
That's exactly what happened
when we lost power
on the Ganges.
These were originally
Cardassian living quarters.
The bed may take
some getting used to.
As an archaeologist,
I've spent half my life
sleeping in tents.
To me, any bed
will be a luxury.
You've obviously
never slept
on a Cardassian mattress.
If you need anything,
just ask the computer.
Thanks, Chief.
Oh, by the way,
how's Jean-Luc?
The Captain?
Mm-hmm.
The last time I saw
him, he was fine.
Well, now that I'm back,
I'll have to look him up.
Really, Vash,
I can't believe
you're still pining
for Jean-Luc--
that self-righteous
do-gooder.
I should have listened to him
when he warned me about you.
You're hurt,
you strike back,
I understand, but
be of good cheer.
I bring you wonderful
news-- I'm back.
And I can see now
it was cruel of me
to leave you.
Very touching, but you
didn't leave me, I left you.
You left me, I left you--
details, mere details.
The important thing is
we're back together
again-- a team.
Joined together at the hip.
Not a chance.
You know you're
going to miss me.
Don't flatter yourself.
You know, I thought
we'd first visit
the Teleris Cluster,
look in on the star
dancers at Mundahla
or maybe head over
to the Lantar Nebula
and view the Sampalo
relic on Hoek IV.
Not interested.
I know-- Vadris III,
charming little world.
The natives think they're
the only intelligent
life in the universe.
No!
All right.
You choose then.
I choose never to go anywhere
with you again, Q.
You don't know
what you're missing.
When we started this little
partnership,
I promised to take you places
no human had ever seen before.
And you have.
It was wonderful.
Thank you.
Now, goodbye.
Two years in the Gamma
Quadrant hardly qualifies
as a grand tour
of the universe.
There's still the Delta
Quadrant to explore,
not to mention all
the other galaxies.
It's over, Q.
I want you out of my life.
You are arrogant,
you're overbearing,
and you think
you know everything.
But I do know everything.
That makes it even worse.
All right, fine.
What is it you really want?
I want the life I had
before I met you.
And a stellar life, indeed.
The eminent Vash--
barred from the Royal Museum
of Epsilon Hydra VII.
Persona non grata
on Betazed.
Wanted dead on Myrmidon
for stealing the Crown
of the First Mother.
Dead or alive.
Preferably dead.
It's a wonder
you haven't offended
every sentient race
in the galaxy.
You're the one who almost got me
killed on Erriakang VII.
And they weren't
exactly thrilled
to see you on Brax either.
What did they call you,
"the god of lies"?
They meant it
affectionately.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I...
Go away.
Q, bring him back.
What business could
you possibly have
with that disgusting
little troll?
I don't know.
You didn't give him
time to tell me.
Now, bring him back
this instant.
All right.
Can I help you?
My name is Quark.
It's, uh, it's come
to my attention
that you have access
to certain... items.
Items that might perhaps
turn a tidy profit?
I'm listening.
For a percentage,
I might be able to arrange
a buyer for your trinkets,
perhaps an auction.
I'll only accept payment
in gold-pressed latinum.
I'll shower you
in it-- 50-50.
Mr. Quark, I believe
you are trying to take
advantage of me.
( laughing )
Some wine?
Oh, oh...
( moaning in pleasure )
You have a talent
for oo-mox.
So I've been told.
I'll not be distracted
by your feminine wiles.
I demand 40%.
All right, 30...
What magnificent cartilage.
22, and don't stop.
You've got a deal.
I expect you'll make
all the necessary arrangements?
Oh, you're good.
You're very, very good.
( sighs )
How perfectly vile.
If that's the sort of company
you kept before meeting me,
it's no wonder
you ended up with Picard.
Go away.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Aren't we the hub
of activity?
( Q disappears )
I'm sorry, am I
interrupting anything?
No, come in, doctor.
Thank you, and please
call me Julian.
Julian, is this
medical business?
Well, to tell the truth,
I tried to come up
with some official reason
for dropping by,
but your excellent health
has robbed me
of any excuses.
Well, that didn't seem
to stop you.
So, I thought I'd contribute
to your good health
by buying you dinner.
Quark's makes
a delicious couscous,
and the company, I hope,
might be mildly entertaining.
Sounds like fun.
Uh, though, I would like
to, uh, freshen up first.
Could I meet you there
in, say, 20 minutes or so?
Those 20 minutes
will seem like an eternity.
These mating rituals
you humans indulge in
are really quite disgusting.
Get out.
You know you don't mean it.
Out!
You're making
a terrible mistake.
You'll be lost
without me.
I can take care
of myself.
Really? Well, we'll
see about that.
( sighs )
Oh, just a cup of mint tea,
please.
( tsking ) You're making
a terrible mistake.
Why? The replicators
haven't malfunctioned again?
I'm talking about Vash.
Stay away from her.
My God, you're
an impertinent waiter.
I'm a friend.
I'm giving you friendly advice.
She's nothing but trouble.
Really? Well, I don't see
that it's any of your
business who I see.
In fact, I'm having
dinner with her now.
Are you sure you're up to it?
You look tired.
I feel fine.
No, no, no, you look
very, very, tired.
( yawning )
Oh, God.
Funny, I...
I do feel a bit...
a bit spent.
Maybe I should...
Maybe I should go lie down
for a, for a minute.
Hopefully, by yourself
for a change.
Bloody hell.
Sir, the Klingon scout ship
has departed Docking Bay 11.
Good. I'll tell Odo
he can relax now.
We've got a problem, sir.
I just saw Q
on the Promenade.
Q here?
What's Q?
A powerful and extremely
unpredictable entity.
I was at a Starfleet briefing
on him two years ago.
Blasted menace
is what he is.
DAX:
What does he want with us?
Whatever it is, you can
be sure we won't like it.
You might ask Vash.
Why Vash?
They know each other.
From the Enterprise?
I believe they actually met
in Sherwood Forest.
It was one of
the little jokes
Q played on
the Enterprise crew.
Main power grid
has dropped 80%.
Sensors are reading
a massive graviton build-up.
How long will it take
to bring us back up
to full power?
It's already beginning
to normalize.
You know, if we have
one of these outages
during a docking procedure,
we could lose
an entire pylon.
I've double-checked
every system.
For the first time in a month
there's nothing wrong
with any of them.
It's got to be Q--
another one of his stupid jokes.
I'm not laughing.
I figured we'd
auction this off last.
Interesting, but hardly
of any intrinsic value.
Really? I thought it was the
best piece in the collection.
Oh, obviously,
my associates have
more sophisticated tastes
than what you're used to,
but, uh, just so it's
not a total loss,
I'll take it off
your hands for, say,
seven bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
It's worth 50 times as much.
( laughing ):
Ridiculous.
All right, 18,
but you must swear
never to tell a soul
about my foolish
generosity.
If you want it, you're
going to have to be
a lot more foolish
than that.
All right, 30.
Now, give it to me.
Bidding starts at 200
bars of gold latinum.
I can't decide
what's more intoxicating--
this Gamzian wine,
or your negotiating skills.
We need to talk.
The lady and I are having
a private conversation.
It can wait.
Tell me, Commander, where
is that doctor of yours?
He was supposed to meet me here
a half an hour ago.
Tell me about Q.
I'll tell you anything you
want to know, Commander.
( whistles )
Just answer one question--
is Starfleet penalizing you
or did you actually request
such a dismal command?
I want you off this station.
Don't be hasty,
my happy-go-lucky friend.
This dreary little gulag
could use a little
color, some excitement.
And who better
to provide that than moi?
Although, I must admit,
I like your new tailor.
I'm not impressed
by your parlor tricks.
These power outages
are going to stop, right now.
Why tell me?
Oh... oh, yes,
of course, go ahead,
blame Q if it makes
you feel any better.
I suppose it's my fate
to be the galaxy's
whipping boy.
Oh, heavy is the burden
of being me.
If you're looking for sympathy,
you've come to the wrong place.
Actually, what I was hoping
for was a little witty repartee
but I can see I'm not going
to get any of that either.
At least your beloved Jean-Luc
knew how to turn
a phrase.
Take a hint, Q.
No one wants you around.
Really, Vash, this playing
hard to get is growing tedious.
Let's not forget that I'm the Q,
and you the lowly human.
I'll decide when
this partnership is over.
Understand?
Why don't you and I
continue this discussion
in private?
Excellent idea.
You're right.
This is an excellent idea.
Sisko to Ops.
All gone.
Bring them back, Q.
Now!
Or what?
You'll thrash me?
Shall we settle
this mano a mano?
Marquis
of Queensberry rules?
What?
Fisticuffs, pugilism,
the manly art
of self-defense.
Come on.
Isn't this all
wonderfully barbaric?
Go on, take a poke at me.
I know that's what you really
want to do, come on.
I'll wager five bars
of latinum on Sisko.
You're on.
Fight back.
This is supposed to be brutal.
You can pay me
out of your profits
from the auction.
You hit me.
Picard never hit me.
I'm not Picard.
Indeed not.
You're much easier to provoke.
How fortunate for me.
Oh! Not again.
Damn it, Q.
Enough is enough.
We're losing atmosphere.
Decompression protocol.
Mr. O'Brien, raise
the confinement shields.
Shields up.
Damage report.
We've got a minor hull breach
in one of the upper bulkheads.
I'm getting reports
of hull fractures
throughout the station.
Emergency systems
appear to be
functioning.
Repair crews
are responding.
The breach was caused
by some kind of focused
graviton pulse.
Every time we've had
a power drain,
it's been followed
by an increase
in the graviton field.
If this continues,
we could wind up
with a breach in one
of our reactor cores.
We'd lose half the station.
Maybe it's time
we opened
negotiations with Q.
I'm not convinced Q
is behind this.
Playing with the lights and
punching holes in the hull
doesn't strike me
as his style.
You wanted to see me?
Make it quick.
I have important business.
Yes, I know.
You're auctioning off
some artifacts
from the Gamma Quadrant.
You were eavesdropping
on my conversation with Vash.
( snickers )
What were you this time?
The table?
One of the chairs?
The wine bottle.
When are you going to realize
that you have
no secrets from me?
I have nothing to hide.
I'm selling quality merchandise
to select clientele.
And what makes
them so select?
They're all
ridiculously wealthy...
and not too bright.
I'll never understand
this obsession
with accumulating
material wealth.
You spend your entire life
plotting and scheming
to acquire more
and more possessions
until your living
areas are bursting
with useless junk.
Then you die.
Your relatives sell everything
and start the cycle
all over again.
Isn't there anything
you... desire?
I have my work.
What more do I need?
A suit of the finest
Andorian silk?
A ring
of pure Surax?
A complete set
of Tanesh pottery?
How about
a latinum-plated
bucket to sleep in?
Ah.
Ahh...
Well, I'm glad to see
you've packed.
I hope you said goodbye
to all your newfound friends.
I don't have
time for this.
You've led a charmed life
these past two years
under my benevolent
protection.
I can take care of myself.
Really?
Do you remember
that tiny little insect bite
you had
on Erabus Prime?
If I hadn't been there...
I am not going with you.
The galaxy
can be a dangerous place
when you're on your own.
It's over, Q.
( groaning )
I leave you now to reconsider
my offer of friendship.
SISKO:
Station Log, Stardate 46531.2.
The station's power is
continuing to be drained
and converted into gravitons.
At this rate, our life-support
systems will fail in 14 hours.
Sir, we'll never find
the source of the power drain
using these bloody Cardassian
internal sensors.
They're just
not sensitive enough.
What if we make the power drain
easier to detect.
If we flood the station
with ionized tritium gas,
we should be able to trace
the particle flow
to the source.
Tritium?
Isn't that pretty toxic?
Only when it's highly
concentrated.
We'd only use
a very small amount.
Do it.
Unless we get this under control
in the next eight hours,
we'll begin
evacuation procedures.
Still chasing your own tail?
Picard and his lackeys
would have solved all this
technobabble hours ago.
No wonder you're not
commanding a starship.
Security to Ops.
Well, aren't we the feisty
little go-getter.
I'd keep my eye
on this one.
Chances are
she's after your job.
Why don't you do something
constructive for a change--
like torment
Cardassians.
Do I know you?
O'Brien.
From the Enterprise.
Enterprise?
Oh, yes.
Weren't you one
of the little people?
Quite a motley crew
you've assembled here, Benji.
My advice to you
is to evacuate now
and save all this
pointless guesswork.
Q, either you tell us
what's going on
or get the hell
out of the way.
I'll tell you
what's going on.
While you're here conducting
futile experiments,
Vash is below engaged
in base commerce
and setting
Federation ethics
back 200 years.
Believe me, gang,
she's far more dangerous to you
than I.
Kolos, my friend.
I don't know
which pleases me more--
your smiling face
or your overflowing purse.
Quark, you obsequious toad.
Your so-called
Gamma Quadrant
merchandise
had better be legitimate
or I'll toss you out
the nearest airlock.
No cause for alarm.
Each piece comes complete
with a statement of authenticity
from Vash--
the Federation's
foremost expert
on the Gamma Quadrant.
In that case, stop sniveling
and give me a synthale.
Are they all
that pleasant?
I don't care
about their manners.
The important thing is
they're honest collectors
of antiquities-- every one.
How honest?
As honest as you and I.
Well, then, we'd better keep
a close eye on them.
My dear, I've been thinking.
What would you say to
a permanent partnership?
What with your knowledge
of the Gamma Quadrant
and my business connections,
we could make a fortune.
Sorry, Quark, but I've slept
in my last tent.
I'm looking forward to a nice,
quiet life back on Earth.
You won't last
a month.
You're like me.
You live for excitement,
adventure and profit.
Not anymore.
Would you care to make
a wager on that?
The graviton field
has increased by 60%.
How soon can we begin
the sensor sweep?
Not until we've increased
tritium levels
to one part per million.
Should only be another
seven, eight minutes.
Commander, we're being pulled
out of our normal position.
Use control thrusters
to stabilize the station.
Firing thrusters.
We're still moving.
O'BRIEN:
If the graviton field
is feeding off
the station's power
maybe we can cut its supply
by shutting down the reactors.
Put life support
on emergency backup.
Take everything else off line.
We're still moving
out of position.
What's our heading?
Bearing 157 mark 13.
Straight into the wormhole.
Now, as you know,
payment must be
in gold-pressed latinum
and all transactions
are final. Hmm?
Remember, bid high,
and bid often.
Ladies and gentlemen,
our first item
is a statue
from the Gamma Quadrant's
Verath system.
Now, I suppose
I should take a minute
to tell you a little bit
about the Verathan civilization,
which reached its height
some 30,000 years ago
and spanned
over two dozen systems
interconnected
by a highly developed trade
and communications network.
This statue
represents Drohlak--
the Prime Ossemite
of the 19th dynasty.
Vash, what are
you doing?
I'm placing the statue
in its historical context.
Give me that.
This isn't the
Daystrom Institute.
Watch closely.
Friends...
it's rare...
it's beautiful...
and it's
a Gamma Quadrant original!
And it can be yours
for the right price.
Bidding will start at ten bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Make it ten.
Fifteen?
Sixteen?
Who will say 17
and be the first to own a piece
of the Gamma Quadrant?
O'BRIEN:
Tritium levels
throughout the station
have reached one part
per million.
Initiating sensor sweep.
We can rule out
the docking ring.
The tritium gas
seems to be draining towards
the central core.
Where in the central core?
O'BRIEN:
Let me see if I can get
a more precise reading.
It's not clear enough.
I can't pinpoint
an exact location.
Based on our
current trajectory...
we'll hit the wormhole
in 18 minutes.
SISKO:
What the hell
could be pulling us
into the wormhole?
Do we have time
to transfer auxiliary power
to the deflectors, Chief?
Sir, there's not
enough power left
to make any difference.
If we get sucked
into that wormhole,
we'll be in a billion pieces
by the time we reach
the Gamma Quadrant.
Sold to Kolos for 36 bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Next, we have...
a dagger...
studded with some
very interesting-looking gems.
Think of it
as a weapon
and an investment.
Bidding will start at 40.
Forty.
Forty-two?
Forty-two.
Forty-five?
Don't hold back.
You know you want it.
Give me 50.
50. We have 50.
I hate to interrupt
such a thrilling display
of naked avarice,
but I thought
it was only right of me
to warn you that this station
is hurtling towards its doom,
and it's very unlikely
that any of you will survive
to enjoy your purchases.
I just thought I'd mention it.
Please, carry on.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I assure you,
everything is under control.
Drinks for everyone,
and free use
of the holosuites
at the conclusion
of the auction, eh?
I don't think I realized
until this moment
how evil you really are.
You would kill
all these people
to get even with me.
Well, I must admit,
the thought had occurred to me,
but this station is
in enough trouble without me,
although I'd be glad
to save you.
All you have to do is ask.
I'll take my chances
with the others.
As you choose.
I'm going to just sit
right here and watch.
I've never seen a space station
torn apart by a wormhole before.
QUARK:
100!
Sold to my cousin Stol
for 105 bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
What if we pumped
more tritium gas
into the central core?
The sensors might
be more accurate
with a greater
concentration.
It might work,
but in four years,
we'd all be dead
from tritium poisoning.
Wait a minute.
Of course.
Bring the reactors
back on line.
The reactors?
But they'll just
feed more energy
into the graviton field.
If we generate enough energy,
it should create a power drain
big enough to trace.
It might also push us faster
into the wormhole.
A lot faster.
It's a chance
we've got to take.
Bring us to full
power, Mr. O'Brien.
Everything you've got.
Aye, sir.
Sold to Rul the Obscure
for 151 latinum bars.
And now...
our final item,
and I think you'll
agree with me
it was well worth the wait.
Bidding will start
at 200 bars of
gold-pressed latinum.
Two hundred?
Can I get 250?
250. 300, anyone?
Three hundred bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Three hundred-fifty?
Here.
Four hundred?
Four hundred.
Five?
Five!
Five hundred and twenty?
Six hundred bars of
gold- pressed latinum.
DAX:
It's not in any
of the crossover bridges
or in the habitat ring.
It's in the upper core.
Three minutes,
14 seconds to the wormhole.
We're picking up speed.
I've got it.
The power drain's coming
from the Promenade.
Chief, you have Ops.
2,500.
2,500, and one.
This way.
3,000 bars of latinum.
My final offer.
3,000 bars!
A million.
A million bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Over here.
A million
going once...
It's by the podium.
A million
going twice...
That's it.
Three times.
This auction's over.
Sold.
Chief, shut down the reactors.
We've found it.
And it's about time, too.
Sorry, all transactions
are final.
This item belongs
to that gentleman over there.
I'm reading a massive graviton
buildup inside this container.
It's increasing
exponentially.
We have to get it
off the station now.
Chief, lock onto my combadge.
Prepare to transport it
500 meters off the docking ring.
But I haven't been paid.
Energize.
SISKO:
Station Log, Stardate 46532.3.
With the embryonic life-form
off the station,
graviton levels
have returned to normal.
We've used
the control thrusters
to return the station
to its original position.
So... you're off to
the Daystrom Institute.
Bet you can hardly wait.
Long, boring lectures,
endless conferences,
whining students
dogging your every step.
Sounds delightful.
Of course...
No, you wouldn't
be interested.
In what?
I hear they've
uncovered the ruins
of a Rokai provincial
capital on Tartaras V.
If you could obtain
some Rokain artifacts...
Forget it, Quark.
I'm going back to Earth.
Have it your way.
Q:
An abysmal place.
Tartaras V?
Earth.
Oh, don't get me wrong.
A thousand years ago,
it had character.
Crusades, Spanish Inquisition,
Watergate.
Now it's just
mind-numbingly dull.
Well, then, by all means,
don't come with me.
I think you'd
be much happier
poking about the ruins
of Tartaras V.
I don't need
your advice.
You really think I...?
You know, I still feel
that I owe you
a million bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Keep it-- just give
me back my life.
You'll regret it if I do.
I'm willing to
take my chances.
All right, if you insist.
But it's not going
to be the same without you.
When I look at a gas nebula,
all I see is a cloud of dust.
Seeing the universe
through your eyes,
I was able to experience...
wonder.
I'm going to miss that.
Well, I guess in some ways,
I'm going to miss you, too.
Maybe I could
drop in sometime.
Oh, God, I hope not.
Hey, Quark.
What's the quickest way
to Tartaras V?
Ah...
I feel as though
I've been asleep for days.
What?
Did I miss something?