The usual, Odo?
Nothing.
The usual.
If all my customers
were like you
my family would be begging
in the Promenade.
Oh, I seriously
doubt that--
not as long as there
is a Miradorn raider
for you to do
business with.
Raider? You mean the Miradorn
ship that just docked?
The raider.
Its reputation, like mine
has probably
been exaggerated.
Anyway, I don't know
the ship or its crew.
You didn't make
your usual welcome call
inviting them in
for a free drink?
The Miradorns are
a quarrelsome people.
I chose to forego
the usual amenities.
He looks away whenever
we make eye contact.
Who?
The new arrival--
the one the Klingons
brought back
from the Gamma Quadrant.
Croden? He's harmless.
Really? How is it you've
come to know him so well?
A man comes in for a drink,
he wants to talk.
He didn't seem to want
to talk much to Sisko
when he arrived.
Who would?
All those Starfleet officers
greeting him at the airlock--
it would scare me, too.
The Federation could
learn a few things
from the Ferengi
about hospitality.
They scared him, huh?
Of course.
I wonder what he has
to be scared about.
( door opening )
Well, now.
I believe a pair
of twinned Miradorn
just nodded your way.
I'm the man behind the bar.
Obviously, they want
to use a holosuite.
You think the whole galaxy is
plotting around you, don't you?
Paranoia must run
in your species, Odo.
Maybe that's why
no one has ever seen
another shape-shifter--
they're all hiding!
I won't have you coming here
harassing my customers.
Order a drink,
play the tables
or vacate the premises!
( softly ):
Rom, bring a flask
of my special langour.
( snarls )
MIRADORN 1:
1,000 bars of
gold-pressed latinum.
MIRADORN 2:
Nonnegotiable.
Ahh.
Oh, very nice.
Unfortunately, uh,
there's a problem.
Problem?
Langour, anyone?
What problem?
The buyer has
backed out.
You guaranteed us a buyer.
A question
has been raised
about the origin
of this bauble.
A similar one was taken
during a raid
on a Vanoben transport
just two light-years from here.
If you had
a bill of sale...
You didn't ask
for any bill of sale
when we contacted you.
You will find another buyer.
A buyer who asks
no questions?
That could take
a long time.
We don't have a long time.
Just stay, stay,
stay where you are, please.
What's this?
Don't fire!
What do you want?
No one is going to get hurt.
Just... just give me that.
MIRADORN 2:
Whoever you are
you're making a mistake.
Well, it wouldn't be the first
and probably
won't be the last.
Give that to me.
( grunting )
( groans )
Security and medical
to Holosuite One.
Five glasses
for four people?
( panting )
He's dead.
My brother.
( door opens )
Take them all
to security.
Yes, take them both
to his office.
Thank goodness
you were close by, Odo.
All of them.
Get out. Go on.
( tricorder beeping )
( steady tone )
Have you known
any twinned Miradorn, Commander?
I haven't met
any before now.
In my species,
we are not just twin brothers.
Together, we are
a single self...
( labored breathing )
two halves of one being.
I am incomplete now.
You should have
considered the risks
before trying
to sell stolen property.
You have no proof.
Two people were killed
on the transport
this object was taken from.
My brother and I
purchased it
from a passing
Altairian trader.
His name?
His ship's identification?
I am the one whose brother
was killed, Commander!
You have only yourself...
I'd like for you to return
to your ship now!
You have my sympathies
but there may
be more questions.
Please don't
leave the station.
I want to deal with the one
who killed my twin.
The law will
deal with him.
My only purpose
in life from here on
is to see him dead.
Well...
can't say I didn't warn
you about Miradorns, Odo.
I assume we
are free to go?
Do you have enough evidence
to hold them, Constable?
As Odo will be
happy to confirm
I was just as concerned
as everyone else
that this was
a stolen objet d'art.
Yes. Curious,
but it's true.
We'll be
on our way then.
You know what else
is curious?
It's curious that Croden
had a Ferengi phaser.
Available in many a port.
And it's curious
that he knew
the Miradorn were
trying to sell you
something of value.
How dare you suggest
that my brother
set up this robbery!
What an interesting
theory, Rom.
If that theory should
ever reach the Miradorn
I'd wake up dead
one morning.
So, I'd appreciate
your not spreading wild
theories about casually.
Lobeless idiot,
next time...
Don't you feed your prisoners?
The fact that you
just killed a man
doesn't affect
your appetite?
It was him or me.
And if he had killed me,
I wouldn't be hungry now.
I want you to understand
exactly what's
going to happen.
There will be a trial
to determine
your guilt or innocence.
We can assign an advocate
or you can request one
from your home world.
I doubt if anyone on Rakhar
would much care.
Really?
Isn't murder considered
a serious crime
where you come from?
On Rakhar,
all crimes are serious...
only there are no trials.
It's a shame that our first
encounter with your species
had to take place
under such circumstances.
I'm sorry if I made
things awkward.
I didn't have much choice.
Why not?
My needs
exceed my skills.
Now, if I had his talents
I would have
no problems at all.
I've never heard
of a changeling
with such
versatility.
A what?!
A changeling, like you.
You've heard
of other shape-shifters
in the Gamma Quadrant?
Haven't they come
through the wormhole yet?
I assumed,
when I saw you...
It's a lie.
He heard me talking
in the bar to Quark.
Well, maybe I dissemble
a little.
"Lie" is a hard word.
But shape-shifters
are harsh
in their judgments.
Feed me
and maybe I'll tell you
where I met someone
just like you.
I don't see
that we have any choice.
We have to contact his planet.
Not the best way
of introducing ourselves.
Homicide as a means
to open relations--
it's not exactly how they
teach it at the Academy, is it?
I think you're
all wrong.
How's that?
They're going
to thank us.
Thank us?
Oh, that's
what I'd do.
He's probably committed
all sorts of crimes
in their system.
They'll be glad to have the
problem taken off their hands.
There's only one way
to find out. Dax?
It won't be hard
to find Rakhar.
According to the logs
Croden was found
in a damaged shuttlecraft
about three light-years
from the wormhole.
There aren't many
M-Class planets in that area.
You're with me.
Major Kira, as long
as the Miradorn ship is here
there's a threat to Croden.
I don't want to have
to tell his people
that he was killed
while in our custody.
I'll have Odo
increase security.
Stop in to see
if I'd run away?
( scoffs )
I couldn't get that lucky.
That Croden
is an interesting character.
I wouldn't know.
Really?
I thought you said
you got to know him rather well.
I never told you that.
I merely said we chatted
when he bought a drink or two.
I've talked to several people
who saw the two of you
engaged in heavy
conversations.
Why, Morn, here, says you even
bought the fellow a meal.
Morn should keep
his big mouth shut.
So what were you
talking to him about?
Just being friendly.
He was...
so out of place
here-- alone.
I felt sorry for him.
You should sympathize
with my kindness.
There's no profit
in kindness.
You attribute odious motives
to my every charitable act.
That's because your favorite
charity is your own pocket.
Speaking of odious motives
I hear you've
been making inquiries
about finding a small ship
to go through the wormhole.
That has nothing to do
with any of this.
I think it does.
I think you were trying
to secure passage
back to the Gamma Quadrant
for Croden
in exchange for staging this
tragic little robbery of yours.
This could turn into
a much bigger tragedy for me
if you don't
keep your voice down.
What did Croden
tell you about himself?
Nothing.
We didn't talk about
anything except business.
Inconsequential things.
What's inconsequential to
you may be important to me.
Did he say anything
about his home world?
No.
Other species in
the Gamma Quadrant?
No.
Security to Odo.
Go ahead.
Ah-Kel and his crew are blocking
the entrance to your office.
Should we clear them out?
Leave it. I'll handle them.
You were told
to stay on your ship.
Understand me, shape-shifter.
He killed the part of me
that made existence bearable.
I cannot stop
until I kill him.
You're not going
to kill anyone.
Get back to your ship
and stay there.
If I find you here again,
I'll lock you up, too.
You've made a lot of friends
in your short stay here.
Well, I guess you'd
know how that feels.
You and I have a great deal
in common, changeling.
We have nothing
in common.
We are both aliens here...
the only ones of our kind.
Each of us is alone
isolated,
shut out.
Others like us
only exist
in the Gamma Quadrant.
I have always wondered
why changelings are so
distrustful of other species.
I doubt the changelings
on your world
would trust you.
Of course not.
There are no shape-shifters
on Rakhar.
You just said...
You implied there were.
I'm sorry if I misled you.
There were shape-shifters
on Rakhar at one time
but that was
centuries ago.
What happened to them?
They were persecuted.
Driven out.
But I know a place
where there are still some left.
Of course,
that was a few years ago.
And if you
had the chance
you'd take me there.
Sure, I would.
Why not?
Tell me where it is,
I'll have a look.
Ah... No, I...
I have to show you.
There is no way that you could
find it on your own.
The next time you lie
I'll save Ah-Kel
the trouble of killing you.
There's that hard word again.
There are times
when I don't dissemble.
Whatever you call it
the truth isn't in you.
From the colony
of the changelings.
We're in orbit.
Open hailing frequency.
Open.
This is the Federation Starship
Rio Grande
attempting to make contact
with the planet Rakhar.
Please respond.
One of your people
committed a homicide
and we have him in custody.
His name is Croden.
I'm picking up a signal
in the southern hemisphere.
They're hailing us.
On screen.
I am the Exarch
of Nehelik Province.
You will transport Croden
to this location.
I'm afraid we haven't
brought him with us.
Your communication
clearly stated
that he was in your custody.
On our space station.
Perhaps I should explain
where we come from.
We are well aware of the traffic
through the newly discovered
passage.
We simply have no interest
in contact with anyone
from your Quadrant.
I am sorry to hear that
but we certainly will
respect your wishes.
We just felt it was necessary
after Croden was arrested.
Croden is an enemy
of the Rakhari people!
We request that
he be returned immediately.
He's scheduled to be tried
for his crime on our station.
Tried? Croden has already been
declared guilty in absentia
for myriad crimes on this world.
That judgment supersedes
your charges.
Return him, and I can assure you
his punishment will be
appropriate to your crime
as well as ours.
I would feel more comfortable
if we could find...
I do not know what kind
of people you are--
I do not care to know--
but if your society purports
to respect the rules
of our society
you will return him
without delay.
Expect him to return
in a vessel just like this one
within 52 hours.
It's an amalgam
of organic material
and some sort
of crystal.
You mean... it's alive.
More or less.
It's almost like
a transitional phase
between organic
and inorganic matter.
I've only seen
one life-form
that even remotely
resembles it.
Me.
In a way...
this stone
might qualify
as a distant
cousin of yours.
Maybe there's a clue
to your origins here.
Where did it come from?
Unfortunately,
the only one who can tell me
is less reliable than Quark.
How do you like
my stone, changeling?
Where'd you get it?
What would
telling you get me?
Nothing.
Ah.
Well, that's too bad.
I was hoping
you'd feel sorry for me
seeing as we're
the only two here
from the other side
of the passage.
I feel nothing for
you but contempt.
You're a thief and a killer,
and who knows what else.
Typical. It's typical.
Of "changeling
behavior"?
Yes, I'm sure.
Uh, excuse me.
In my sector
there is a nebula
called the Chamra Vortex.
There are millions
of asteroids in it.
I found this stone
on one of them.
I could take you to it,
changeling.
Others must know
where it is.
No, no, the Vortex
is uncharted but, as a thief
and a killer and who knows what,
I hid there often.
I found this colony
of changelings by chance
and I know my way back.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Yes, Commander?
Constable, I want you
to escort the prisoner
back to his home planet.
He's... not to stand trial...
here?
Croden apparently
committed crimes on Rakhar.
His government is adamant
and the Bajorans have agreed
to release him.
We're going
to have trouble
getting him past
the Miradorn.
Yes, I know.
Ah-Kel's been
screening every ship
leaving this station.
How soon
can you be ready?
I'm ready now.
There's a Rigelian freighter
leaving here for the Gamma
Quadrant in an hour.
Maybe we can use them
to run interference
between you
and the Miradorn ship.
I'll move the prisoner
to the runabout right away.
Constable, once you're
on the other side
you'll be on your own.
The Miradorn vessel can
outrun any of our runabouts
and, if they
do come after you
a warning from us will
just point an arrow to you.
Understood.
So you're finally
taking me up on my offer.
I'm taking you home.
O'BRIEN:
Commander.
The Rigelian freighter's
ready for departure.
Signal Odo.
KIRA:
The Miradorn ship
is scanning the freighter.
Doesn't look like
they're reading the runabout.
How do you stand it,
changeling?
Living where you don't belong?
Are you happy?
I'm as much a part
of the place
as anyone else.
Oh, I doubt it.
They tolerate you,
but you're not one of them.
Being what you are
you can pour your square shape
into a round hole
but you don't
really fit, do you?
You're like my stone.
I think
I finally figured out
what crime you were
found guilty of on your world.
What's that?
You talk too much.
( laughs )
Maybe you're right.
Perhaps that is
how it started.
Perhaps I asked
one question too many.
Anyway, that's as good
an explanation as any.
Explanation
for what?
For why they
came that night.
I was never told, and,
to this day, I don't know.
They broke into my home
just before dawn
and, before I had time
to stop them
they had murdered
both my wives.
You see...
on my world
the punishment for being
an enemy of the people
is the death
of your family.
I had no
sophisticated weapon...
only a short slaughter knife
that I used for cutting
the necks of fowl
that we would
prepare for supper.
Imagine my surprise
when I discovered
that the necks
of the security officers
were no more difficult
to cut than the birds'.
Even the sound they made
as the blade crossed
their gullets were similar.
You expect me
to believe this
appalling tale?
Would it make any
difference if you did?
No.
Well, then believe it
because it's true.
Oh, my return
will be celebrated, changeling.
They'll be very grateful.
You'll be a hero.
Perhaps
you might even use this
as an excuse
to exchange envoys.
If you don't stop talking
I could sedate you
for the rest of the trip.
Sorry. I didn't...
I didn't know I bothered you.
AH-KEL:
Get in there!
He's going to kill us!
He says we were in with Croden.
Where is he, Quark?
Croden? He's in security.
You're lying!
( gasping )
He's gone!
You're hiding him.
You've been in this
together all along.
You're as responsible
for my brother's death as he is.
Ah-Kel, no.
This is Odo's doing.
Don't you see?
He wants to turn us
against each other.
Why should
I believe you?
Tell me
where Croden is
or you can die
in his place.
I don't know
where he is
but maybe
I could find out
if you'll
just release me.
( gasping )
Get me the security chips.
Level four clearance.
( snapping fingers )
It isn't at all clear...
The coordinates
are very clearly stated
right here in the log entry.
One more thing,
little Ferengi--
you better be telling me
the truth
or I'll be back...
to finish this.
Oh, you are clever,
brother.
Now Ah-Kel will rid us
of Croden and Odo.
Unless Odo is sensible,
and gives up his prisoner.
Oh, no!
Then Croden would tell Ah-Kel
the truth about our plan.
We're dead. We're dead.
You shouldn't have told
him how to find them.
Be quiet.
Odo will never give up
his prisoner.
He'll just
get himself killed.
Do you really think so?
Oh, get out of here,
you fool!
Get!
Yes, Chief?
The Miradorn ship
is leaving the station.
Major, do whatever
you can to delay them.
Ops to Miradorn ship...
please hold your position.
Stand by for
departure instructions.
No response.
They're still moving.
Dax, how long
before Odo reaches Rakhar?
Just over five hours.
KIRA:
Miradorn vessel...
you are in violation
of Bajoran transit regulations.
Please return at once
to the docking ring.
They've increased power
to their thrusters.
On screen.
You'd save time going
through the Vortex.
It's a long way
around it.
Aren't you the
least bit curious
about your
own people?
Of course, I am.
Unfortunately,
I don't have the liberty
of pursuing that curiosity
right now.
They don't maintain
a humanoid shape, you know.
They refused
to assimilate
on my world.
They're a proud species.
That's why
they were so persecuted.
But I will say this for them--
they treated me
well enough
when I landed
at their colony.
I was badly wounded.
They could have
allowed me to die.
They didn't.
You're one of them.
That's for sure.
You have the sense
of decency, of justice...
You don't give up, do you?
( beeping )
( explosion )
Computer, what was that?
COMPUTER:
A temporary loss of stability
resulting from the impact
of a concentrated plasma charge.
We're being attacked?
COMPUTER:
Affirmative.
Pursuing vessel approaching
from 181 mark 12.
Put it on the monitor
and identify.
COMPUTER:
Miradorn vessel, Theta class.
He's hailing us.
AH-KEL:
The first shot was a warning.
You will surrender
the Rakhari prisoner to me.
I don't give up my prisoners,
Ah-Kel.
Very well.
Then you can die with him.
( explosion )
COMPUTER:
Warning. Damage to shields.
Computer,
evasive maneuvers!
COMPUTER:
Warning. Shields at 41%.
Your computer's
not going to outsmart him.
I'm a security chief,
not a combat pilot!
Then give me the controls!
You?!
I can get us
through the Vortex.
The ionized gasses
would screen us
from his sensors.
Drop your suspicious nature
for a minute, changeling.
Can't you see?
It's our only chance!
( grunts )
Why are we
slowing down?
The Vortex is riddled
with volatile pockets
of a gas
we call toh-maire.
If we destabilize them
they could ignite,
and blow this ship apart.
You really have been
through here before.
Sometimes I do tell the truth.
How do you remember
what's true and what isn't?
( explosion )
I thought you said they couldn't
detect us in here.
He must be following
our impulse wake.
Computer,
disengage impulse engines.
Go to thrusters.
COMPUTER:
Acknowledged.
Thrusters engaged.
What are you doing?
Once our impulse wake drops off
he might try to pick up
the discharge of our thrusters.
We'll be better off if we land.
So, changeling
I guess I'm going
to take you home after all.
Hurry! This way!
ODO:
Croden!
Slow down, Croden!
Stay where I can see you.
Croden!
What's your hurry?
What's in here?
I told you--
the colony.
Anxious to see
them again, are you?
Yes. Of course.
Whatever it is you came
here for, you can forget it.
We're leaving.
No!
Now!
How much of it was true?
Any of it?
Any of it?!
No. No.
On Rakhar, we tell stories
about changelings.
I thought they were
myths until I met you.
The stone!
I have no idea
where it came from.
Rakhari merchants
buy stones just like it
from off-world traders.
It's used as a key.
A key to what?
To my only reason
for living.
And it's ahead,
in that cavern there.
Please, help me.
There's been a cave-in.
What is it?
A stasis chamber.
It's my daughter.
The only member
of my family I could save.
Help me.
It shapes itself
to fit the lock.
( hissing )
( door opens )
Father?
I was dreaming about you.
I'm here now, Yareth.
You don't have to dream anymore.
Hello.
This is Odo.
He's a security officer.
No, no, he's not
going to hurt you.
He's going to take you
to a place
where you'll be safe.
Won't you?
Where are you going?
I'm going home.
But you can't.
They'll kill you.
Yareth, I must answer
for my crimes.
But all you did was
try to protect us.
Their sensors must have
picked up our life signs.
We've got to get
back to the runabout.
Odo!
Is he badly hurt?
There's no way to tell.
I don't know anything
about his species.
I'll carry him
back to the ship.
What's the matter,
Father?
( explosion )
Nothing, darling.
Nothing.
Go! Go!
( moaning )
You're heavier
than you look.
You could have left me behind.
Don't thank me.
I already regret it.
I haven't been able
to lose them.
Sooner or later,
one of his photons
is going trigger
a toh-maire explosion
and kill us all.
Let me have the controls.
Find us one of those
toh-maire fields.
I just told you,
you don't want to go
anywhere near one changeling.
Find us
the closest toh-maire field.
Six degrees to starboard.
Changing course.
He's chased us everywhere else.
Maybe he'll follow us
in there, too.
His sensors may not be able
to detect
how volatile the field is.
If he fires on us in there,
the whole thing will ignite.
That's what I'm counting on.
Set a course
along the interior perimeter.
Done.
Computer, shut down all engines.
COMPUTER:
Engines disengaged.
Maintain emergency readiness
to reengage impulse
on my command.
We're an awfully easy target.
He's hailing us.
On screen.
Are you prepared
to surrender your prisoner?
I have a full array of Starfleet
weapons trained on you, Ah-Kel.
Frankly, I don't
know much about them
but I understand they
equipped this little vessel
with some
pretty powerful stuff
so I suggest
you withdraw
while you still can.
There will barely be a trace
of your little vessel
when we are finished with you.
He's coming about.
Powering
his shields.
His starboard photon bank
is armed.
Computer, engage!
He's firing photons.
( alarm bleeping )
Is everybody back there
in one piece?
Yes.
Good.
Take us out
of your precious Vortex.
I only have one
last favor to ask.
Yareth is going to be
alone on your world
just as you've
always been.
She's going
to need someone
to look after her.
If you're asking me
what I think you're asking...
We know you could use
some company, changeling.
You'll deny it, but we
both know it's true
or this stone would have
meant nothing to you.
COMPUTER:
Incoming subspace signal.
Vulcan band frequency.
On screen.
Starfleet Runabout
this is the Vulcan Science
Vessel T'Vran.
Are you in any difficulty?
Chief of Security Odo
from DS9.
We're fine, Captain.
We detected a major eruption
in the Chamra Vortex.
I was afraid a small ship
like yours
might have suffered damage.
I appreciate your concern.
What's your course?
To the wormhole,
then home to Vulcan.
I've beamed over two survivors
from a ship
that wasn't so lucky.
I have to complete a mission.
Could you give them
transportation to Vulcan?
Easily done.
We will rendezvous
with you shortly.
Prepare for transport.
Don't thank me.
I already regret it.
How?
How will you explain
not delivering me?
I'll tell them you were killed
when Ah-Kel torpedoed
the asteroid.
This dissembling
must be catching.
You're going to have
to get used to living
in an alien society.
Like you...
but I know
where my home is
and perhaps, someday
I'll be able
to go back again.
I hope this helps you to
find where you came from.
VULCAN CAPTAIN:
T'Vran to Ganges.
Ready for transport.
Stand by.
Are you really a changeling?
Yes...
I suppose I am.
Go on.
We don't want to keep
the Vulcans waiting.
Energizing.
Computer, set a course
for the wormhole.
Course laid in.
Ready engines.
Home.
Where is it?
Someday we'll know...
cousin.
Engage.