I thought I told you
to cancel that order.
Now, what am I supposed to do
with 5,000 wrappages
of Cardassian yamok sauce?
They're the only ones
who could stomach that swill.
Hey, Nog, are you going
to play or what?
You ordered it,
you're going to pay for it.
I'm going to take
half your paycheck every week
for the next six years!
From now on, no more
Cardassian food in here
ever!
Come on, Nog, it's your turn.
5,000 wrappages.
That's a lot of yamok sauce.
Look, either
take your turn, or I win.
It'd be a shame
to let it go to waste.
That's it... game over.
Jake, I'm getting
that tingling in the lobes
and when a lobe tingles,
it means only one thing...
opportunity.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about
gold-pressed latinum...
maybe four or five bars.
I thought you were
talking about yamok sauce.
You've got a lot to learn
about opportunity.
Come on.
Where?
Station Log, Stardate 46844.3.
With the help of the Federation
Bajor is about to commence
its first large-scale
energy transfer...
the tapping of the molten core
of its fifth moon, Jeraddo.
Magma pressure's
remained constant.
Differential subsurface
movement is at 0.3 percent.
Is that good?
They'd tell you if it weren't.
Oh, uh, why is that
red light blinking?
We're in normal standby mode.
Oh, I take it, then, we're not
expecting any surprises.
We don't like surprises
any more than you do.
Minister Toran, these
people are professionals.
Forgive my bureaucratic
nit-picking, Major
but we're counting
on Jeraddo's energy
to heat a few hundred thousand
Bajoran homes this winter.
And, with that in mind
we're due to make
our next inspection.
Anyway, so there I was,
sitting in Quark's
when Morn just comes over to me
and invites me for dinner.
Grid square 12-delta
reads clear of life-forms.
Morn?
Are you serious?
Beginning scan
of grid square 15-delta.
So, what did you say?
I said I was busy.
Good.
But you know those seven
or eight little wiry hairs
that come out of his forehead?
What?
Well, they make him
look kind of cute.
That's odd.
Sensors read a humanoid presence
in 15-delta.
Could be one
of the project thermologists.
Not in 15-delta.
Look for yourself.
All the inhabitants
were supposed to be
evacuated by now.
Well, I better beam down there,
take a look around.
Ready to transport.
I won't be long.
The problem is,
they don't like uniforms.
Neither do I,
but it comes with the job.
Which is?
Do we talk, or do they attack?
You're halfway pretty.
Does that mean I can come in?
No. No, I don't like
uniforms either.
I'm scared of them.
See, we had our fill
of uniformed bullies.
I'm no Cardassian.
You know you were supposed
to be out of here by now.
All I know is this farm, girl.
Now, you want proof,
just look at my crop.
Uh, I'd rather you
didn't call me "girl."
It's mostly katterpod beans
but you won't find
better katterpods.
My father always said
you get bigger katterpods
when you spray in
some chlorobicrobes.
Is that right?
Well, that could be.
Your family's farmers then?
No, but if I don't get
on your good side soon
my arm's going to fall off.
Yeah, pretty eyes like yours
deserve a meal.
You come on in.
I'm afraid we don't have time.
Look, obviously,
you were overlooked
in the general evacuation.
I got to get you out of here.
We'll talk about that
over supper.
Come on.
There he is.
220, bottom price. 220.
Excuse me, sir.
Are you the Captain
of the Lissepian cargo ship?
That's right.
And you do a lot of trading
with the Cardassians.
Why not?
One thing about Cardassians...
they pay their bills.
Yes, I've heard that.
I have also heard
they love their yamok sauce.
Look, if you're trying to buy
some yamok sauce from me, boy
you're wasting your time.
I'm not carrying any.
We're not buying,
we're selling.
5,000 wrappages of it.
Original, not replicated.
Where would you two boys
get all that yamok sauce?
We have connections.
5,000, you say?
And they could be yours for, say
five bars of
gold-pressed latinum.
That's a lot of latinum.
That's a lot of yamok sauce.
Look, I'm not carrying
any latinum
but I'll tell you what I'll do...
I'll trade you something for it.
We were counting on latinum.
Hold on.
What would you trade?
I'll give you 100 gross
of self-sealing stem bolts.
Some Bajoran ordered them
from me, and now he can't pay.
Self-sealing stem bolts?
Top-grade merchandise.
You won't find a better
stem bolt in this sector.
I don't think so.
We deal strictly in latinum.
Nog, are you sure?
What are we going
to do with stem bolts?
to do with yamok sauce?
Sir, I have discussed
it with my partner
and you have a deal.
Good.
I'll meet you at Cargo Bay 9
at 2100 hours.
We'll make the trade then.
Now, the question is,
what are we going to do
with a hundred gross
of self-sealing stem bolts?
I have a better question.
How do we get
your uncle's yamok sauce?
At least you're not the type
that's going to dispossess
a man on an empty stomach.
Wouldn't think of it.
Well, that's good,
'cause these roots
are going to take
three hours to soften.
What?
You wouldn't want to eat your
roots hard, now, would you?
I'm in no hurry.
Kira to Ganges.
This is Dax.
Are you all right?
A man with a talent for delay
has just invited me
to a farewell supper here.
You go on.
I'll have one of
the thermologists bring me back.
Enjoy supper.
Dax out.
Here you go.
You wash it off first
and then you scrape
the skin off.
You don't talk much.
Oh, they don't talk at all.
The Cardassians
took care of that.
They escaped up
to this moon 18 years ago.
I've been here 40.
We did real well together.
Oh, get out the plates
and utensils like a good girl,
would you?
That cupboard right over there.
You know, you look real good
even from this angle.
But you know something?
You walk
like a carnivorous rastipod.
Now, look...
You're trying to make me mad.
How am I doing?
Not well enough
to get rid of me.
Damn!
Well,
what do they call you, dear?
I'm Major Kira.
I'm in charge of evacuating...
Your given name.
Nerys.
Well, Nerys, I'm Mullibok.
And these roots are really going
to take three hours to cook
so you might as well
just sit down
and relax yourself, child.
It's going to be tasty.
Mullibok...
they begin tapping the core
of this moon in seven days.
I know.
You are only three people.
This project is going
to benefit thousands...
hundreds of thousands.
I made myself unconcerned
with that 40 years ago
when I escaped
from a Cardassian labor camp
on your precious Bajor.
What we're trying to create now
is what you weren't allowed
to have then.
It can be your Bajor, too.
This is where I live.
This is my home.
You can have a home on Bajor
with people to welcome you
and your friends.
Life will be different, yes,
but it will be fine
really.
No, it won't.
I told you, my life's here.
If I leave here, I'll die.
So I'd rather die here.
Dabo!
Uncle Quark!
You.
Last night, that dabo player
who dropped his drink?
I saw you run
and get him another one
without charging him.
I warned you
about picking up
your father's habits.
It'll never happen again, Uncle.
You know, I was trying
to find some storage space
for the shipment of lokar beans
that are due in tomorrow.
Is it okay if I stack them
on top of the yamok sauce...
if I can reach that high?
Please don't talk to me
about yamok sauce.
Do you want me to get rid of it?
I could take it
to the matter reclamation unit.
Anything.
Just get it out of my sight.
Nog... you're a good boy.
I stowed away aboard
a Cardassian survey vessel
which was making stops
all through the Bajoran system.
They were looking
for possible mining sites.
Anyway, when we got here
to Jeraddo
I overpowered the crew
and I stole whatever I'd need
to start building a life here.
You overpowered the crew?
Yourself?
There was only six of them.
That was fortunate for me
because I was somewhat weakened
by the captivity and starvation.
Anyway, here I was
the first person ever
to settle on this moon
and the only trouble was
that I didn't have
any kind of farm implements.
So, once again, starvation and I
were staring each other
in the face.
Uh... I'm not boring you?
No, no.
I want to hear who won.
Ah.
Well, it was mind over matter.
Every 26 hours
I'd just tighten up
my waist belt another notch
and, that way,
my belly didn't know
that it was shrinking.
Excuse me?
You asked me to tell you
how I got started here
which I'm very
politely trying to do.
Now, will you
kindly let me finish?
I assume you found some food
before you ran out
of belt notches.
Are you telling the story
or am I?
By all means.
I can't wait
to hear how it ends.
Obviously, I was going
to have to plant
and harvest a crop.
So I did what
any person would do
who had to build
an entire world for himself.
First, I rolled back
and forth on the ground
till it surrendered.
Then I got down
on my hands and knees
and I started to plow
using nothing but
my fingernails, mind you.
I plowed every furrow
in that field
straight as a plumb line.
Now, that is inventive.
Yeah. If I came across a deposit
of mineralized clay
what I'd do is just
grind it up in my teeth.
That way, it enriched the soil.
Baltrim, how about some
of that wonderful wine here?
What I'm telling you, Major...
I tamed this place.
Me.
I believe you.
You look like a bit
of a fighter yourself.
Well, on Bajor, we had to be.
To get rid of the Cardassians,
huh?
Mindless butchers.
We paid them back.
I bet you did.
They probably didn't
know what hit them.
I'm sorry I missed the fun.
Fun?
Must have been like spearing
kandippers in a bottle.
Wait a minute.
Are you serious?
You know what
the Cardassians were like...
what weapons they had.
We didn't stand a chance
against them.
How did you beat them then?
Well, we beat them because...
because we hung on
like fanatics.
Hung on like fanatics.
I got to remember that.
Mullibok, listen to me.
One of these days
I'm going to have
to finish up that kiln.
Then I can temper my baking pots
put some colorful
lids on them.
That'd be nice, wouldn't it?
I appreciate your trying
to hang on here.
I sympathize,
but you can't stay here.
The minute they start
tapping the crust
it will release carbon
and sulfur compounds.
It will make
the air unbreathable.
The Cardassians
probably told you
you didn't stand
a chance either.
Did you surrender?
No.
Why do expect me to act
any different than you?
Now, you tell them
they can start
cracking this moon apart
whenever they're ready.
I'll be here.
I'll tell them.
So that's a stem bolt.
A self-sealing stem bolt.
There's a difference.
You're sure about that?
What's important is that
it's top-grade merchandise.
You can't get a better
stem bolt in this sector.
And we have
a hundred gross of them.
That's a lot of stem bolts.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Anyone know what
this cargo's doing here?
It belongs
to my Uncle Quark.
They're stem bolts.
Will you do me a favor,
and tell your uncle
we're getting a little weary
of him bypassing
import procedures.
I'll certainly do that, sir.
It's just that my Uncle Quark
really needed some stem bolts.
You mean
self-sealing stem bolts.
That's right!
That's it!
Self-sealing stem bolts.
Well, he sure needs
a lot of them.
It's top-grade merchandise.
You can't find a better
stem bolt in this sector.
Oh, I don't doubt it.
What does he need them for?
Uh, the usual.
The usual?
Well, you know.
Why does anybody use
self-sealing stem bolts?
I wouldn't know.
I've never used them.
Never?
I've never even seen one.
Then how do you know
they're self-sealing?
I read it here
on the manifest padd.
I would have bet anything
that he would have
known what they were.
I told you, we should have
asked that freighter captain.
Wait.
I know who could tell us what
self-sealing stem bolts are...
the Bajoran who ordered
them in the first place.
His name's got to be
on the shipping codes.
Sirco Ch'Ano.
It has his address
and everything.
You think he'll be mad
that we have his stem bolts?
He couldn't afford them.
Remember?
But we'll offer to sell them
to him at a discount.
I'm glad you finally
made it back.
I was getting worried about you.
Is he alone?
I think Minister Toran
is in there with him.
Even better.
I don't understand.
There were 47 other people
living on that moon.
They all left willingly.
How do we know?
All we know is that they
obeyed the order to leave.
And so will these people.
You haven't met Mullibok.
Is there anything
you can offer that might
make him more willing to leave?
Not a thing, believe me.
Would a postponement help?
Give us time to work
something out with him.
We can't postpone.
And, if he stays,
he'll be committing suicide.
We'll have to beam
him off the surface.
If we take him like that,
we'll be killing him.
I refuse to allow
three stubborn holdouts
to jeopardize a project
that will benefit
so many of our people.
I am sorry, Major.
If there was anything else
that we could do
we'd have done it.
But there is another way.
We can tap the core using
phased energy retrieval.
I thought we'd agreed
phased energy retrieval
would take too long.
It would mean
waiting a full year
before we can extract any
meaningful amount of energy.
I wish we had the time
to be more delicate
but we don't.
So, instead, we'll act
like Cardassians.
Easy, Major.
I resent that.
It's obvious to me
that you've developed
a feeling for this man.
Fine, I can accept that.
But if you're not comfortable
with completing this assignment
I'll find someone else who is.
That won't be necessary.
Mullibok?
What about the other two?
They, uh, have a cottage
35, 40 meters through there.
Now, remember, these people
were victims of the Cardassians.
They don't speak.
They're very frightened
of uniforms. Understood?
Understood, Major.
If, uh, you find them
working in the fields
just gather up their clothes
and supplies, I guess.
Without permission?
We're not going to get
their permission.
Just be very careful
with everything.
You plan to use that?
Protocol.
If you like, I'll help
you pack your things.
You sent those two uniforms
after Baltrim and Keena.
That's right.
I'm doing what has to be done.
Me, too.
Don't make us take you by force.
Please.
I promise you,
it won't be so bad.
You can plant whatever
you want to on Bajor.
Stay by yourself
if you want to... that's fine.
Take some seeds with you
for those terrible roots
of yours I had to eat.
Just listen to reason.
Listen to yourself, Major.
Tell me what you hear.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean, you sound
like a two-headed
Malgorian I knew
when I was a boy.
You ever try to talk
to a two-headed Malgorian?
This is no time
for one of your stories.
See, the thing with
two-headed Malgorians is
that it can never figure out
what it really wants to do
and that can be very
confusing, believe me.
You know, eventually,
you're going
to have to stop talking
and deal with this.
And the trouble
with my Malgorian friend
was he had all kinds of problems
and he couldn't decide
how to solve them.
So he'd always
come running to me
so I could solve them for him.
Mullibok...
You know what I finally
said to that Malgorian?
I said, "Fellas, deal
with it yourselves." Hmm?
Fine.
I'll pack your things myself.
Major!
They're crazy!
This man just stuck me
with a farm implement.
And she attacked me from behind.
Let her go!
Stay back!
No!
You!
Beam up to the runabout
and call the station.
Get Dr. Bashir.
Move!
I still can't see you.
What did you say your name was?
I'm getting some kind
of subspace interference.
My name's...
We're the, um, the Nog and...
the Noh-Jay Consortium
and we have 100 gross
of self-sealing stem bolts.
And we were wondering...
You have my stem bolts?
What would you want for them?
We'll let you have them for...
five bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Five bars?!
Four bars.
I don't think I...
Three bars.
If I had any latinum,
I'd already have the bolts.
Would you consider an exchange?
I would consider
one bar of latinum.
He doesn't have any latinum.
Let's exchange for something.
I don't want "something."
I want latinum.
I can't hear you.
Can I interest you
in a piece of land?
Land is good.
For what?
It's nothing but dirt.
How much land?
I can let you have
seven tessipates.
Seven sounds good.
First yamok sauce,
then stem bolts
now tessipates...
and still no profit.
We're getting closer.
I can feel it.
You can?
I think so.
Do we have a deal?
We'd have to see proof
that you own the land.
Naturally.
You'll get the transmission
on that by 1200 hours.
You just bought yourself
some stem bolts.
Land.
Dirt.
Just rest easy.
You took a phaser blast
which punctured your peritoneum.
It's serious.
And if you try to move around,
you'll make it worse.
Another uniform.
Dr. Julian Bashir, Starfleet.
Major Kira sent for me.
She did, huh?
You're backwards, Nerys.
I told you.
With me unconscious
she could have swept us all
off of here
with no trouble at all.
My friends Baltrim and Keena?
They've been evacuated to Bajor.
I'll be taking you back
to our station, so I can...
No.
I stay here.
He refuses to leave.
Really?
Well, he's got to be cared for.
I'm going to take him
without his permission.
No, you're not.
Well, he needs close attention.
I'll be here.
There's no medical facility
here.
Leave the instructions
and whatever medication
you think he'll need.
She didn't offer a word
of explanation, sir.
She simply removed
her uniform tunic
and started building.
Well, Doctor
right now she stands
a pretty good chance
of being out of uniform
permanently.
I'm going
to tell Minister Toran
that she's remained
temporarily on Jeraddo
at your request.
But, sir, that isn't true.
Make it true, Doctor.
Now, please.
Commander, I'd advise that
Major Kira remain on Jeraddo
for humanitarian reasons...
How long?
The next day or two.
For the next day or two, sir.
Thank you, Doctor.
I will consider that request.
Dismissed.
What's that?
It's for deep bruises.
Don't ask me why it works.
I'm not the doctor.
What are they going to do
to you for staying here?
Probably the same thing
they're going to do to you.
I don't really know.
What are you so angry about?
When I was very small
I remember there was this tree
right outside my window.
It was the ugliest
most gnarled and battered
old tree I'd ever seen.
Even the birds
stayed away from it.
But you loved it, huh?
Hated it.
Because it had grown so huge
its branches blocked out the sun
for kellipates
and its roots buried themselves
so deep in the soil
nothing else could grow there.
Oh, it was a big,
selfish, annoying...
Nasty...
Nasty... nasty old tree.
Hmm.
Sounds to me like it had
a lot of character.
A lot.
So what happened?
Did you cut it down?
I don't know yet.
Sisko to Kira.
Commander.
I'm preparing to beam down.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Major, either I'm coming down
or you're coming up.
He doesn't have much faith
in you, does he?
Nerys.
This is still my home.
What do you want?
I'm here to see Major Kira.
Well, she doesn't
want to see you.
Neither do I.
Wait a minute.
Don't speak for me.
You know, you're causing
a lot of trouble.
I can't tell you how delighted
I am to hear that.
How many of you
Federated uniforms
you going to send after me?
40, 50?
I don't think
it will come to that.
That depends on how bad
you want to get rid of me.
Mr. Mullibok, I'm here
because I'm concerned
about my First Officer.
What about her?
By staying here,
she's jeopardizing her career.
Would you go back to bed?
You quit telling me what to do.
Major
can I see you outside
for a minute?
Talk to him as long as you want.
Why don't you tell him
the story about your tree?
Be quiet.
There was this big,
ugly tree, uh...
Go on.
Never mind.
I can see why you like him.
What can I do for you,
Commander?
You and I have a material
subsistence report to finish
by the end of the week.
I don't think I'm going to
be able to help you with that.
It's part of
the liaison officer's job.
I know.
I don't like the prospect
of having to break in a new one.
You have a job to do here, Major
and you're not doing it.
It's not that simple.
I'm not saying it's simple.
I'm saying it can't wait.
Look... I understand
you're used to sympathizing
with the underdog.
You've spent your life fighting
to overcome impossible odds
just like he's doing.
But you have to realize
something, Major.
You're on the other side now.
Pretty uncomfortable, isn't it?
It's awful.
When I first met you, Major
I thought you were
hostile and arrogant
but I was wrong.
Bajor needs you, and I need you.
I like you
and I don't want you to be hurt.
So, as a friend,
I'm here to remind you
that his fate
is already decided.
Yours isn't.
Thank you.
There will be a runabout
standing by.
One to beam up.
Mullibok.
No!
You're...
you're hurting her.
Let go.
Easy.
Lussilla...
I told you...
take your hands off me.
That's right.
It's okay.
Everything's going to be fine.
Oh...
it's you.
You were having a bad dream.
Not just a bad dream...
bad memories.
I didn't say anything,
did I?
No.
You thirsty?
Hungry?
No. Leave me alone.
Go back to sleep.
Where you going?
I'd like to get some sleep, too.
Fine, bring the chair over here.
Well, are you my nurse, or not?
Is this better?
Are you going to talk all night?
Let me sleep.
Nog, I'm waiting.
I'm thinking.
About what?
Latinum, and how
we don't have any.
All we have is dirt.
How many times do
I have to tell you?
It's not dirt... it's land.
What are we supposed
to do with this land?
Sell it, I guess.
To who?
Why do I have
to think of everything?
We should have kept
the stem bolts.
Land is better than bolts.
How do you know?
You can build things on land.
You can't build anything
without bolts.
Just throw down a card.
And you say they're based
here on the station?
That's correct.
The Noh-Jay Consortium?
No, never heard of it.
Why do you ask?
I was contacted
by a government
official this morning.
They want to build
a reclamation facility
on a strip of land owned
by four different people.
Three of them
have agreed to sell
but the government
doesn't know
how to reach the fourth...
this Noh-Jay Consortium.
You mean the government
can't build
without that one piece of land.
Apparently not.
What a wonderful
opportunity for profit.
I told you that land
was better than bolts.
And you think I'm part
of this Consortium?
I think very little
goes on here
without your knowledge.
True. This time, however
someone has failed
to include me.
Are you telling me
you're not involved?
Oh, not yet,
but that will be remedied.
You can tell the Bajorans
I'll be opening negotiations
with them shortly.
Let's see.
Who on this station
is clever enough?
Uncle Quark?
Not now.
But, Uncle Quark...
Go sweep the floor.
It's important.
All right, make it fast.
I have a business opportunity
that might interest you.
Huh?
It'll only cost you five bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Nog...
Any pain?
Just a little sore.
I was starting to think
you'd sleep all day.
That's because I was taking care
of you all night.
I don't recall
asking you to do that.
I can handle this.
Go get something to eat.
There isn't time.
You're finally leaving?
Last one.
I didn't think
I'd ever finish it.
It's finished.
Nothing to do but fire it up.
What's all this?
You finished your work.
Now I have to finish mine.
But you don't want to.
I could use a friend on Bajor.
I'd like it to be you.
As long as that cottage
is standing, I stay here.
What the hell are you doing?!
Saving your life.
So you chose your uniform
over me after all.
That's not true.
The time
I've spent here with you
has meant so much to me,
but it's over.
It's time we went on
with our lives...
mine and yours.
You say you're my friend.
Prove it.
Use that weapon on me.
I can't.
If I leave here, I'll die.
No, you won't.
I won't let you.
Two to beam up.