( door chimes )
Come in.
Commander,
I just received word
that a Valerian transport
has requested permission
to dock here at the station.
Let me guess.
You're here to recommend
that we deny that request.
The Valerians ran
weapons-grade dolamide
to Cardassian forces
during the occupation of Bajor.
I'm aware of that.
I believe
they're continuing
to ship weapons
to the Cardassians--
weapons that could eventually
be used to attack Bajor.
I share your concern, Major,
but unless we have proof
to back up those charges...
The proof is on that ship.
Let me conduct a search
and if I find any dolamide,
we can confiscate it.
I'm afraid it's
not that simple.
Dolamide is used
for power generators
reactors and short-range
transports.
And for weapons.
Only if it's
extremely pure.
So we're going
to do nothing?
I didn't say that.
We just can't
board their ship
and start
tearing it apart.
Well, what can we do?
You bring me evidence
that the Valerians
are dealing in weapons-
grade dolamide
and I promise you that
the Federation will use
every kind of diplomatic
pressure to stop them.
You really think that'll work?
It will if the Valerians
want to continue trading
with the Federation.
All right.
We'll try it your way.
Good.
Then you will see to it
that the Valerian ship
is cleared for docking.
Yes, sir.
Chief, I have a subspace message
for you from your wife.
They've arrived
safely on Bajor.
Imagine taking
11 bored school kids on a visit
to the grain-processing center
at Lasuma.
I'm glad it's not me.
Major.
Here's the information
you requested
on the Captain
of the Valerian ship.
Let me know if you
find anything else.
DAX:
Sensors are reading elevated
neutrino levels at the wormhole.
Something's coming through.
On screen.
Kira to Sisko.
You better come out here.
DAX:
It's the Klingon
Vessel Toh'Kaht.
KIRA:
They weren't due back
for another month.
Open hailing frequencies.
( console beeping )
I'm reading
a transporter signal.
Somebody must have beamed off
the ship just as it exploded.
Mr. O'Brien?
Something's interfering with
the rematerialization process.
DAX:
Lock onto him
with our transporter signal.
Try boosting
the annular containment field.
I'm already there.
( gasping )
He's been hit
by weapons fire.
It's severe.
We've got to get him
to cryostasis.
Victory.
( groans )
( tricorder beeping )
( steady tone )
He's dead.
SISKO:
Station Log, Stardate 46922.3.
We have identified
the dead Klingon.
His name was Hon'Tihl,
First Officer of theToh'Kaht.
Why he died, and the cause
of the ship's destruction
is still unknown.
I found
tritanium alloy fragments
in his chest and upper arms.
If that were all,
we could have saved him
but those weapon burns
were too severe.
Is there any way
to identify
the kind
of weapon used?
I'm running a microtissue
analysis right now.
I should have the results
in a couple of hours.
The Klingon said
"victory" just
before he died.
I wonder what he meant.
According to
Klingon High Command
the Toh'Kaht was
in the Gamma Quadrant
on a routine
bio-survey mission.
"Victory" during
a bio-survey?
As I recall, the Toh'Kaht put in
for a maintenance check.
Ask around the station
and see what you can learn
about this bio-survey.
Dax and O'Brien, I'd like the
two of you to take a runabout
and try to find the Toh'Kaht's
mission recorder.
I want to know what caused
that ship to explode.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant?
Yes?
You coming?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
( laughing ):
Never mind.
( console beeping )
Damn it, not yet.
Deep Space 9, this is
Valerian Vessel Sherval Das.
We are entering
the Bajoran system.
Clear us for docking.
Negative, Sherval Das.
There's going to be
a slight delay.
We are in need of maintenance.
It's been a long journey.
Oh, I'm sure it has,
but we have our own problems.
You'll just have to wait.
Stand by, Sherval Das.
I'd like an explanation.
I wasn't finished running
a background check
on their ship.
We agreed there
would be no delays
in the docking procedure.
They just visited
Fahleena III and Mariah IV--
the same two stops
they used to make
when they were running
dolamide to the Cardassians.
The last stop would be
the purification plant
at Ultima Thule.
Now, if I can place them there
then we know they're running
weapons-grade material.
SISKO:
Your ship has been
cleared for docking.
Thank you, Commander.
Sherval Das out.
No delays.
ODO:
So, Quark
I heard you had some
problems with the Klingons
the last time
they came through.
Spare me from beings
who think pain is pleasure.
In small doses, perhaps,
but the Klingons
oh, they're hard
on the holosuites.
They wreck the furniture.
I'm still fixing the
walls of Holosuite 6.
I'm not saying
they don't spend big.
I'm just saying, by the time
you figure in the damage
I'm lucky to break even.
They do tend toward
bluster, don't they?
Throwing their weight
around, bragging...
This crew was worse
than the last.
A glorious mission!
I said, "What's so glorious
about a Gamma Quadrant
bio-survey?"
And, uh... what did they say?
Crafty tonight, Odo,
aren't we?
Looking for clues about
the fate of the Klingons?
If I tell you what I heard...
what do I get in return?
The chances are
what you heard won't help
so why should I give you
something for it?
Because otherwise,
I heard nothing.
That damaged holosuite--
work crew seven
is probably doing the repairs.
Am I right?
Uh-huh.
Well, it looks as though
I might have to put in
a priority request
for work crew seven.
The bulkheads in security
could use
a little shoring up.
They said...
they'd be coming back
through the wormhole
with something
that would make the enemies
of the Klingon Empire tremble.
Their exact words?
Direct quote.
You've been most helpful.
Don't let it get around.
( shrieking )
( choking )
( screaming )
Odo?
Dr. Bashir!
( gasps )
Welcome back, Constable.
How am I?
How do you feel?
Fine.
Good, because I have
no way to know.
Your body chemistry
defies analysis.
I don't remember anything
but I'm back to normal?
Well, like I said,
you tell me.
I don't know
what caused it
and I couldn't tell you
if it'll happen again.
In fact, there's really
nothing more I can do here.
Then thank you
for your time, Doctor.
Tell me, Odo.
Do you share my concern
over this Valerian situation?
Concern?
I think you know what I mean.
Why don't you tell me.
Then you can be sure I know.
Just don't be surprised
if the uneasy alliance
on this station
starts to show a few cracks.
What uneasy alliance?
Commander Sisko and Kira.
Mark my words,
there's going to be trouble.
What exactly are you basing
all this on, Doctor?
Very clever, Constable.
But you're probably right.
It's a little too early
to commit oneself either way.
Are you finished with me?
Well, unless you'd like
to pour yourself
through my phoretic analyzer.
I'd love to see the results.
Another time, perhaps.
I've got them.
Who?
The Valerians.
Their ship was at the Ultima
Thule station one week ago.
That confirms it.
They're definitely
running dolamide.
So?
So I've got an armed team
ready to board their vessel.
Confiscate the material
and send them back
where they came from.
Frankly, I'm half-tempted
to take them to Bajor
and press charges.
By whose authority?
You're not going to do
anything about this.
I'm not...
and neither are you.
That ship is acting
against Bajoran interests.
This station
is Bajoran property.
Commanded
by a Federation officer.
Commanded by me.
Are you challenging that,
Major?
No, sir.
Good.
Short-range sensors
are picking up some debris.
Looks like
duranium alloy.
Probably pieces of the
Klingon secondary hull.
It's possible
their mission recorder
is somewhere in the debris.
The magnetic field
from the duranium
could be masking it.
Let's get a little closer.
Major Kira's become
awfully aggressive
toward Commander Sisko
lately about station policy.
An honest
difference of opinion.
What if it's more
than a difference of opinion?
What if Kira thinks the Bajorans
don't need us on DS9?
It is their station.
That would be suicidal.
Without a Federation presence,
Bajor would be vulnerable
again
to the Cardassians.
Well, that doesn't mean
there aren't plenty
of misguided Bajorans
who think they
can go it alone.
You've become quite friendly
with Major Kira, haven't you?
Have I?
Well, yes, I suppose I have,
if you say so.
Well, I wouldn't get
too friendly with the natives,
if I were you.
Remember
where your loyalties lie.
Of course.
Benjamin and I have been close
for a long time.
Hand and glove.
I'm on his side--
no question about it.
That reminds me
of the time we found...
Good.
Anyone who's against Sisko
is against me.
( console beeping )
I'm picking up
a weak subspace
transponder signal.
It's the mission recorder.
Constable.
Can I help
you, Major?
Oh, you always manage
to help me, Odo.
In fact, I think we work
pretty well together
you and I.
Yes, I suppose
our relationship
has always been...
cooperative.
Exactly.
And that's just what
I need right now--
your cooperation.
I'm convinced the Valerians
have dolamide on board
but the evidence is
still circumstantial.
I need solid proof.
I want you to slip
past their
security systems
and into their
cargo bay.
I heard that Commander Sisko
was adamant
about not interfering
with the Valerian ship.
Has he changed his mind?
Yes.
How odd.
Very well.
I'll keep the two of you
informed about my progress.
That won't
be necessary.
Commander Sisko's very busy.
No sense in disturbing him.
I can't fool you, Odo.
You wanted me to go
behind Sisko's back, didn't you?
Forget it.
Bad idea.
What if you had
to choose sides?
Just remember who
your friends are.
Personal Log, Miles O'Brien.
Stardate 46923.1.
We've managed to retrieve
a portion of
the Klingon officer's journal.
Of course, Major Kira
heard about it immediately.
She must have spies everywhere.
( static ):
I believe the Captain
has gone insane.
He executed
two more crew members...
( garbled )
...medical officer...
... my quarters...
...violence
is being created by those...
energy spheres we brought back
from Saltah'na.
Believing him
to be the Captain's spy
I slit...
I've seen enough.
There's more.
Klingons' mission
must have failed.
That failure caused
problems on board.
I couldn't care less
what happened to a Klingon ship.
O'BRIEN:
Well, the Klingons
might want to know.
Dax and I have set up
a data interpolation
to fill in
what's missing.
It might take some time.
SISKO:
If you have to.
The search itself
is often reward enough.
Benjamin, do you
remember that...
Fine.
Do whatever you have to do.
Don't bother me with it.
Ah...
Here we are.
A Modela aperitif.
It's bright and sweet.
Much like yourself,
Lieutenant.
I'll put it
on your tab.
The bad flattery's
on the house.
The two loveliest
creatures on DS9.
I must be living correctly
to be so...
so blessed.
What can I do for you, Major?
Get lost.
As you wish.
How are you, Lieutenant?
You know what they say--
put the shoe
on the right foot first
but put the left foot first
into the bathtub.
I understand.
But what I really
meant was...
are you happy?
That's not a question
I get asked very often.
Oh, but it should be.
In my opinion
you are the most valuable
officer on this station.
May I?
Please.
Not bad.
For Quark.
It is good.
I couldn't imagine running
this station without you.
Are you trying
to tell me something?
( sighing )
My disagreement
with Sisko
over the Valerians
is no secret.
Well, you know how he gets
once he's made a decision.
Yeah, it's
like talking to a stone.
I remember a time...
on Rochani III
we were cornered
by a party of Kaleans
who were not very happy
to see us, but Benjamin...
Y-You told me this
story this morning.
Oh.
I suppose I did.
If you were to talk
to Starfleet Command
tell them how displeased
the Bajorans are
with Sisko's handling of this.
I know they'll listen to you.
I was decorated
on my very first mission.
The Admiral was a Vulcan.
So during
the presentation ceremony...
Dax.
We have to keep
the Valerians here
until we can search the ship
and confiscate the dolamide.
You've got to convince
Starfleet.
It's for the good of Bajor...
and the Federation.
I've been friends
with Benjamin Sisko
for... many years.
In many ways,
he's like a son...
or a nephew.
Some kind of close relative,
anyway.
Jadzia, listen to me.
I'm getting rid of Sisko,
one way or the other.
Don't force me to get
rid of you as well.
( crashing )
Would you like to join us?
( gasping ):
Let me go!
What did you hear?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Good.
( door opening )
( groaning )
Is this a Ferengi fashion
I'm not aware of?
Kira tried to tear
my head off.
( groaning )
I want to file charges.
Tell me about it.
I heard her plotting.
Go on.
She tried to convince Dax
to take her side against Sisko.
( groaning )
And did Dax seem persuaded?
What difference does that make?
I was attacked!
Answer the question.
I... I couldn't tell.
She was on the fence.
Doesn't Kira's behavior seem
a little out of the ordinary?
And the others...
at the staff briefing,
Sisko was bored
as if he couldn't be bothered
about running the station.
And Bashir...
since when is he so concerned
about station politics?
Don't look at me that way.
I'm perfectly normal.
Yes, I suppose you are.
It's time
I had a talk with Sisko.
Odo, wait!
Odo!
QUARK:
Wait, Odo!
Odo!
I want satisfaction!
KLINGON:
We have... battle
for decks... 12.
...armory... in the hands...
Captain Tel'Peh
...my death.
But still, I... confident
...gain control
of this ship.
I am weakened by my wounds.
Sisko?
...my enemies closing in.
Still... hide...
( chiming )
Come in.
KLINGON:
First Officer's Journal, Day 26.
Where's Commander Sisko?
In his quarters
where he's safe.
Still... been able to hide
a thalmerite device
under... beam near
the reactor... deck 26.
Rather... taken prisoner
I will blow up this ship
and transport to safety.
Perhaps Medical Officer Kee'Bhor
was correct.
Our... began when we opened
those energy spheres.
All I know
is that Captain Tel'Peh
must die!
Journal closed.
Sounds like
there was a power struggle
on board.
Some sort of attempted takeover.
Management by mutiny.
Standard operating procedure
on a Klingon vessel.
But awfully unusual
for a Federation-run
space station.
Don't worry.
If Major Kira tries anything,
we'll be ready.
When will the other log entries
be available?
At the current rate
of processing, it'll take
at least seven more hours.
But the computer's taking it
one entry at a time.
I'll set it up
so you can access it as it goes.
Thank you, Chief.
Of course,
Constable.
Don't the Commander and I
always try to make you happy?
What are you doing here?
Chief O'Brien's orders.
SISKO:
Come in.
Commander.
Hello, Constable.
How are you today?
Concerned, sir.
On such a fine afternoon?
How inappropriate.
Commander, I think
something might be wrong
with... some of us.
Ever since the Klingon ship
exploded
and their First Officer
beamed over
certain behaviors and attitudes
have been... abnormal.
( clearing throat )
There appears
to have been
a mutiny on the
Klingon ship.
I wouldn't go
so far as to say
the same thing is
happening on DS9
but I... do find some
disturbing parallels.
If something's
bothering you, Odo
tell it to Mr. O'Brien.
That's what he's there for.
What do you think?
What is it?
A clock.
Fascinating, isn't it?
It's not nice
to keep a friend waiting.
Did we have an appointment?
When have I ever had to stand
on ceremony with you, Odo?
I need your help.
I took care of the Valerians.
What do you mean?
I locked down
their docking clamps.
That ship isn't leaving
until I say it is.
O'Brien will need at least a day
to do anything about it.
By then, it won't matter.
You're going after Sisko.
And O'Brien.
Either we get a more reasonable
Commander from Starfleet--
someone we can control--
or we go it alone.
With me running this place
you will be able to do
what needs to be done.
If you want to toss
Quark out on his ears
toss him out.
If you want to proclaim
martial law
on the Promenade,
proclaim it.
This station will be yours
to protect
with no interference.
What's your plan?
Oh, Odo...
I trust you more than
anyone on this station
because you can't
be corrupted.
But this is
a dangerous time.
I can't take any
chances, even with you.
When the time comes
you'll know it.
I'll be counting on you.
Computer, open a channel
to Starfleet Headquarters.
Subspace communication
to Federation territories
is currently unavailable.
Why?
By authority of Major Kira.
Ah...
Open a channel
to the Bajoran Council.
Communication to Bajor
is currently unavailable.
By authority of Chief O'Brien.
That is correct.
Computer, are you finished
reconstructing the journal
of the Klingon First Officer?
Data interpolation is complete.
On screen.
Computer, scan the journal
for mention of contact
with any alien race.
One entry found.
Play it.
First Officer's Journal, Day 22.
Exploration of the fifth planet
proved to be a waste of time.
This world is not worthy
of a Klingon colony.
All we found were
a collection of energy spheres
which possess some type
of telepathic archive.
The spheres described
an ancient power struggle
that destroyed a race
called the Saltah'na.
We will forward our results
to our science division.
O'BRIEN:
Kira's already locked
down the Valerian ship
and she's diverted
half the station's systems
to her control.
Since when?
An hour ago.
I've heard some
disturbing rumors
from our people
on the Promenade.
I think she's going to make
an attempt on your life.
I want you to arrest them--
Kira and every Bajoran
officer on this station.
I want the name
of every sympathizer.
That's not
a good idea, sir.
There's a lot more of them
than there are of us.
If we tip our hand,
it might work against us.
What can we do?
Leave the station.
Never! Get me a phaser!
I'll get rid of Kira!
Hear me out, sir.
We leave the station,
raise a Federation attack force
and return.
And, on that day
we'll get rid
of all your enemies.
How do we proceed?
I'll need a few more hours
to free up the Valerian ship.
I've already talked
to their Captain.
He's more than happy to take us
back to Federation space.
( whispering ):
Call me as soon as you're ready.
It'll take effect
in two minutes.
Plenty of time
to get a good...
( door opens )
Plenty of time for you
to get a good night's sleep.
Thank you, Doctor.
Chronic insomnia.
I think it's hormonal.
So, how are you?
I take it you've completed
your autopsy of the Klingon.
Of course.
You know, Odo
events have been moving
rather rapidly
since our last conversation.
I'd advise you
to choose sides now
or risk finding yourself
without any friends at all.
The Klingon, Doctor--
what did you find?
He's still dead, if
that's what you mean.
I don't have time
for jokes.
Your findings could determine
who controls this station.
How?
All in good time.
First, tell me
about the Klingon.
Well, I found
nothing very unusual.
The columnar cells
in his brain stem, perhaps.
The membrane permeability
was off.
What could cause that?
Any number of things.
Could it have something
to do with telepathy?
The Klingons were studying
the telepathic archives
of an ancient race.
If those archives
were contained
in a self-sustaining
energy matrix
that could explain the changes
in the Klingon's brain.
Could that energy matrix
have somehow caused them
to reenact the power struggle
that destroyed the Saltah'nans?
Possibly.
What are you getting at?
Doctor, I believe
the Klingon
brought the matrix
with him
and everyone in Ops
was affected except me.
Without a humanoid brain,
my system rejected it.
An interesting theory,
Constable
but I'm certainly not behaving
out of the ordinary.
Of course not
but what if you and I
are the only two
who aren't affected?
Do you think we could use this
to our advantage?
Exactly.
Tell me your plan.
The first thing we have to do
is figure out
how to remove the field
from everyone affected.
Then we'd lose our advantage.
Would you prefer that someone
blew up the station?
I see your point.
The power to control
the energy matrix
is the power
to control this station.
If I could determine the natural
resonance frequencies
of this telepathic field
I might be able to generate
an interference signal
which could drive it out.
Do it.
I promise, Doctor,
you won't regret it.
O'Brien,
what's taking so long?
Almost there, sir.
We've got one more level
of security lockouts
to break through
and the Valerian ship
will be ready to go.
Commander, I have
the report you asked for
on those weapon scanners.
Give it to Mr. O'Brien.
I really think you
should see this, sir.
Commander!
Dax to Kira.
Is it Kira?
Did Kira put you
up to this?
No.
I want the truth!
Is that clear?!
Let's see how this works.
Put it down...
sir.
Take them.
Dax, you were supposed
to deactivate the transporter.
I forgot.
Damn it, Kira must have
set up a force field
to keep us from beaming
onto the Valerian ship.
The transporter
rerouted us here.
We've got to get
to that ship.
Odo's our only chance.
He might be able
to override the field.
You're sure we
can trust him?
I don't see
that we have any choice.
Sisko to Odo.
Odo here.
Kira has moved against us.
She has Dax on her side.
We need your
help, Constable.
You've got to clear us a path
to the Valerian ship.
Take Crossover Bridge 1
to the cargo bay entrance
into Docking Port Four.
I'll keep it open for you.
Right. Sisko out.
Leave your combadge here.
Don't look so
worried, Chief.
She hasn't beaten us yet.
Yes, sir.
They're still
in Airlock Corridor 6.
What could they
be doing in there?
Maybe they've given up.
Sisko would
rather die...
which is fine with me.
Oh...
they must have taken
off their combadges.
That's all right.
They won't get far.
Someone's taking out
our force fields.
KIRA:
Whoever it is knows how
to override the security codes.
Kira to Odo.
Go ahead, Major.
Whose side are you on,
Constable?
Yours, of course.
Really?
Then why are you helping
Sisko escape?
On the contrary.
You'll find him trapped
in Cargo Bay 4.
Consider it my gift to you.
Oh, my apologies.
We'll see you there.
Kira out.
Well done.
You certainly fooled her,
didn't you, Constable?
We're running out
of time, Doctor.
I'm just about finished.
I've set up an ionic
interference signal
in Cargo Bay 4,
calibrated to lock on
to the resonance frequencies
of the telepathic field
and drive it out
of all those affected.
And what will happen
to it then?
Well, it'll remain suspended
as long as the interference
is in effect.
That's all I
need to know.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
It's been sealed.
I wouldn't do that, sir.
You might run into Kira.
She must have realized we
removed our combadges by now.
It's completely locked down.
Someone's activated
a level-5 security protocol.
There's only one other person
on this station besides yourself
has that kind of access.
Odo!
KIRA:
Relax, Commander.
He'll be here any minute.
So, this is how it all ends.
For you.
You know what disturbs me?
The ingratitude.
I offered you my kindness,
my help, my leadership
and how do you repay me?
With betrayal.
But you won't
get rid of me so easily.
You see, unlike you,
I understand history.
My name will blaze
across the stars
long after your petty
treacheries have been forgotten.
But you won't
be here to see it.
Major, wait!
Glad you two could make it.
Computer, execute Odo One.
( electrical humming )
( gasps )
( groaning )
Constable?
Everybody grab hold
of something secure.
( beeping )
( bay door opening )
( hissing )
Welcome back, everybody.
Commander's Log,
Stardate 46924.5.
With nothing to contain it
the telepathic matrix
has dispersed in space.
Meanwhile, I'm happy to report
everything and everyone
aboard DS9
has returned to normal.
Did you really build that?
Apparently so.
Why?
I have no idea.
I know that none of us
was really responsible
for our actions, but...
I feel I owe you an apology.
For attempted mutiny.
Well...
yes.
I think we'll let it go...
this time.
( ticking )