We never cared what we did
as long as it annoyed
the grown-ups.
All inner deflector
shield subsystems
are showing equal intensity.
Power balance levels
are reading normal.
I was a champion window breaker.
On a dark night with a few
rocks, I was deadly.
Um, which you are
you talking about?
We're being hailed
by an incoming freighter.
Open a channel.
On screen.
Welcome to DS9.
I'm Major Kira Nerys.
This is the Kobheerian Freighter
Rak-Miunis
requesting permission to dock.
Docking Port 6
is clear for approach.
Thank you.
We have a passenger on board
requiring medical assistance.
Can you tell us what's wrong
with your passenger?
He says it's a condition
called Kalla-Nohra.
It's apparently chronic
but he doesn't have
his medication.
Beam him directly
to our Infirmary.
We'll have our doctor
standing by.
Thank you, Commander.
Rak-Miunis out.
Dax to Infirmary.
This is Bashir.
Go ahead.
A Kobheerian transport is
about to beam a patient to you.
He's suffering from something
called Kalla-Nohra.
I'm not aware of it.
I'll check the computer.
Commander, I'd like to go
down to the Infirmary
and meet that patient.
Of course. Why?
The only cases
of Kalla-Nohra I know of
were the result
of a mining accident
at a Bajoran forced labor camp
that I helped liberate.
The survivors of Gallitep
have always been a symbol
to us of strength and courage.
By all means, Major.
Take as much time as you want.
Ah, Major.
I'll be right with you.
Kira to Odo.
Go ahead.
I'm in the Infirmary.
I need security here
on the double.
I'm on my way, Major.
What's the matter, Major?
Your patient is a criminal.
Good afternoon.
I assume this is the problem.
Problem?
Lock him up.
This is outrageous.
On what charge?
Will somebody tell me
what's going on?
This man needs medical care.
Then give it to him
in his cell.
I haven't done anything.
Then why did you run?
I'm trying to get away
from this Bajoran fanatic.
The look of hate in her eyes...
she'd like to kill me.
Oh? And why would that be?
Well, it's obvious.
I'm a Cardassian.
He's not just any Cardassian.
He's a war criminal.
So you're saying this man...
what's his name?
Marritza.
Aamin Marritza.
You're saying Marritza's
on the Bajorans' list
for Cardassians wanted
for war crimes?
He's not on any list
I've seen, Commander,
and I've got them all.
I don't care
whether he's listed or not...
Hold on, Major.
Marritza is traveling
on a Federation ship.
He comes here
for a medical emergency
and we throw him
into a security cell.
I, for one, hope he's listed.
Commander, I know what I've
done isn't exactly policy
and may not even be legal,
but it's right.
All right, Major,
what do we charge him with?
I'm charging him with having
contracted Kalla-Nohra.
Do you want to explain
that to me?
The only way he could have
contracted that condition
was to have served
at the Gallitep labor camp
at the time
of the mining accident.
So, that makes him a war
criminal, just being there?
Commander, if you'd been
there 12 years ago
when we liberated that camp...
if you'd seen the things I saw...
all those Bajoran bodies,
starved, brutalized...
Do you know
what Cardassian policy was?
Oh, I'm not even talking
about the murder.
Murder was just the end
of the fun for them.
First came the humiliation.
Mothers raped in front
of their children
husbands beaten
until their wives
couldn't recognize them
old people buried alive because
they couldn't work anymore.
I think I'll have a talk
with our guest.
I'll come with you.
No, Major.
It'd be better
if I spoke to him alone.
How do you feel?
Better, thank you.
I'm Benjamin Sisko.
I'm in charge of this station.
Oh, finally.
The Federation to the rescue.
Are you going to get
me out of here?
I hope so.
Tell me, how did you contract
Kalla-Nohra Syndrome?
I don't have Kalla-Nohra.
I have Pottrik Syndrome.
The freighter captain said
it was Kalla-Nohra.
A very similar condition.
Take the same medication,
as a matter of fact.
Then you didn't serve
at the Gallitep labor camp?
Labor camp?
No.
I've never been to Bajor.
I was a military file clerk.
I reside now on Kora II
where I boarded a freighter
which, unfortunately
for me, came here.
Now, Commander, if you have
no more questions
I'd like to be on my way.
Am I still drunk
or am I in jail
with a Cardassian?
Odo!
You're not keeping me
in here with one of those.
Odo! Odo!
I put myself in your hands,
Commander.
Let me get this straight.
You're saying
Marritza does have Kalla-Nohra?
There's no doubt about it.
He has all the symptoms.
And when I ran a lower pulmonary
bio-probe, he read positive.
And you're sure he doesn't
have Pottrik Syndrome?
Yes, absolutely.
If he had Pottrik's
the bio-probe
would have been negative.
Then he was
at the Gallitep labor camp.
Definitely.
I've cross-checked all Bajoran
and Federation medical records
and there's simply no other way
he could have gotten
this condition.
Kira to Sisko.
Yes, Major?
Commander, there's an incoming
transmission for you from Bajor.
It's the Minister of State.
Thank you.
If you'll excuse me, Doctor.
Minister Kaval.
Good day, sir.
And to you, Commander.
I trust you're in good health.
Things are going well
on the station?
Quite well, thank you.
That's wonderful.
I'm told you've performed
a special service
for Bajor today.
Congratulations to you.
I don't quite follow.
You're not holding
a certain Cardassian for us?
We are holding a Cardassian
temporarily.
By temporarily, you mean
until you are satisfied
that a verified identification
has been made.
Minister, I'm not sure
we have the grounds
to hold him that long.
I fully understand
your concerns, Commander
but since our Major Kira
has accepted responsibility
in this matter
the burden
is off your shoulders.
I don't agree.
Commander
if this Marritza was at Gallitep
we want him,
and we will have him.
Is that clear?
It is.
Good.
We'll chat again soon.
Good day, Commander.
May I join you?
Actually, I was just about
to pay a visit to our friend,
Marritza.
That's what I want
to talk to you about, Major.
I'd like Odo to handle
this investigation.
Why?
He's our Chief of Security.
Minister Kaval put me in charge.
Minister Kaval
doesn't run this station.
And the Federation has no right
telling us how to deal
with our criminals.
If it turns out
that he is a criminal
then he'll be yours,
and you're welcome to him.
Until then, he's just a traveler
under suspicion.
You think this is all
some personal vendetta
on my part, don't you?
I think you're too close
to be objective, yes.
You're right.
I'm not objective.
But I'm your First Officer,
and I give you my word
I will conduct myself
accordingly.
You once said we were friends.
I'm asking you now,
as a friend...
please, let me conduct
this investigation.
I owe it to them.
You mean the victims.
That's right.
The ones who moved too slowly
and never moved again.
I'm asking for all the Bajorans
who can't ask.
Let a Bajoran do this.
Sisko to Odo.
Go ahead.
Constable, Major Kira
will be in charge
of the Marritza investigation.
I understand.
Thank you.
Constable.
It's about time you let me out.
Try to stay out of trouble
for a day or two, will you?
I'll do my best.
Oh, and Odo, let me know
when you hang the Cardassian.
I've begun a background check
on Marritza.
So far he is what he says he is.
He boarded that Kobheerian
freighter at Kora II
where he's worked
as an instructor
at a military academy
for the past five years.
Keep looking.
Don't worry, Major, I intend to.
I'll be with the prisoner
if you need me.
My compliments
on your replicators, Major.
But the sem'hal stew
could use a little yamok sauce.
I'm glad you're enjoying it.
I doubt that, Major.
I doubt it very much.
I hope it won't disturb
your dinner
if I ask you a few questions.
If I refuse to answer?
I'll ask them anyway.
Of course.
This is my job.
Persecuting Cardassians goes
far beyond your job, Major.
It's your passion.
You claim you were never
at Gallitep.
I missed that honor.
And that your illness
is not Kalla-Nohra.
Again, true.
Again, false.
Our Doctor confirmed
you do have Kalla-Nohra
which means
you were at Gallitep.
If your lies are going to be
this transparent
it's going to be
a very short interrogation.
Well, in that case, I'll try
to make my lies more opaque.
What was your rank at Gallitep?
What were your duties?
You don't want to know.
Just answer the question.
You'll be disappointed.
I'll risk it.
I had the distinction of serving
in the exalted position
of filing clerk.
Filing clerk?
I told you
you'd be disappointed.
Actually, I would have preferred
to avoid military service
altogether
but I had the good fortune
to be posted
to the records office
at Gallitep
and I turned out to be
an exemplary file clerk.
In 14 units of service
I never misplaced
or lost a record.
I received
numerous commendations.
Gul Darhe'el, himself, called
my computer filing system
"a masterpiece
of meticulous exactitude."
Well, there you are.
My secret's out.
My crimes laid bare.
I await execution.
I hope we don't
keep you waiting long.
You know, I never heard
of a filing clerk
becoming an instructor
at a military academy.
Until now.
What did you teach?
Believe it or not, filing.
I can verify that.
Be my guest.
I still think you're a liar.
So much for our search
for the truth.
Now we trade insults.
You admit
you worked under Gul Darhe'el.
We all did.
I take it, then,
you witnessed the atrocities.
Atrocities?
What atrocities?
Oh, I vaguely recall hearing
a scream from time to time.
Atrocities? No.
You expect me to believe
you knew nothing of the murders,
the tortures?
You never saw the bodies?
Of course I saw bodies.
People died all the time
at Gallitep...
mining accidents, illnesses,
feuds among the workers.
You're saying
Bajorans killed each other?
At times.
Over food, a blanket, a woman.
The conditions were harsh.
It was a labor camp, Major.
I helped liberate that camp.
I saw the bodies.
I know how they died.
You saw
what we wanted you to see.
Who do you think
started the rumors
about brutality at Gallitep?
It was Gul Darhe'el himself.
Now, there was a leader.
Brilliant, extraordinary man.
He knew that to rule by fear
was to rule completely.
Why bother
with actual mass murders
when just the reports
of such incidents
would have the same effect?
Which was?
You know as well as I do, Major.
To keep you Bajorans thinking
of yourselves as victims.
To keep you afraid and helpless.
Turns out
we weren't so helpless.
We did get rid of you.
Leaving was
a political decision, Major.
I've enjoyed
reminiscing with you.
Now I think it's time
you let me out of here.
I can't do that.
Oh, no, no, no, no,
of course not.
No, you see, you're the one
who's lying now, Major.
It's not the truth
you're interested in.
All you want is vengeance.
Commander, I was led to believe
the Federation guarantees
the safe and unrestricted
passage of all travelers
visiting your station.
That's correct.
Then, how do you explain
the detention
of a Cardassian citizen?
Marritza came here seeking
medical attention.
Right now, he's
under our Doctor's care.
All we're trying to do
is to verify his identity.
A simple matter... if you'll
give us some assistance.
I assure you, Commander,
you don't need our assistance.
If this patient says
his name is Marritza
then that's who he is.
I hope you're not suggesting
you don't trust him
simply because he's Cardassian.
I don't trust him
because he's already lied
about being at Gallitep.
Is that what you're charging him
with, Commander?
Lying?
So far, we haven't charged him
with anything.
Then let him go.
I'd like nothing better.
But first, I need to know
who it is I'm letting go.
I do appreciate
the awkwardness of your position
here, Commander.
This Bajoran obsession
with alleged
Cardassian improprieties
during the occupation
is really quite distasteful.
I suppose, if you're a Bajoran,
so was the occupation.
I might remind you
that neither one
of us is Bajoran
and I would hate
their bitterness
to cause conflict between
Cardassia and the Federation.
I hope to avoid that, too...
with your help.
You don't need my help
to safeguard one Cardassian
citizen on your station.
If any of these
Bajoran hate mongers
get their hands on him
I'll hold you
personally responsible.
What are you looking for?
Answers.
Found any yet?
Marritza says I don't care
about the truth.
That all I want is vengeance.
Are you worried
that maybe he's right?
All I want
is to see him punished.
Even if he is just a file clerk?
That's just it.
I don't want him
to be just a file clerk.
I want him to be...
I don't know...
something worse.
You want him to be guilty.
As far as I'm concerned
if he was at Gallitep,
he is guilty.
They're all guilty.
His punishment
will let Bajor feel some...
satisfaction.
It sounds like
you're trying too hard
to believe what you're saying.
You already know,
if you punish him without reason
it won't mean anything.
And you already know
vengeance...
isn't enough.
Reroute the signal
enhancement module
to the main sensor array.
Aye, sir.
How's it look?
Just give me a second.
I'll run a diagnostic.
I've checked
with the Bajoran Archives
and they do have
a Marritza on record
as being a filing clerk
at Gallitep.
I've also checked with the
military academy on Kora II.
Marritza has been
teaching filing there
just as he claims.
All set, Commander.
Major, how many images were sent
from the Bajoran archives?
Only one.
It's the only picture
they could find of Gallitep
that had Marritza in it.
The Cardassians destroyed
almost all records
of the occupation.
The image enhancement
and transformation functions
are patched directly
into your console.
Major, what if this image
confirms
that Marritza was a file clerk?
What do you expect us
to do then?
I suppose you'll let him go.
I'm glad we understand
each other.
I've got it.
On screen.
Which one is Marritza?
Let's see... according
to the caption
he's the one
in the background
in the far right.
Isolate and magnify.
You're going to have
to do better than that.
Give me a minute.
I'm running an image
enhancement sequence.
It's not him.
Are you sure
we're looking at the right man?
Background, far right,
Aamin Marritza.
It can't be.
If that's Marritza,
then who are we holding here?
Lieutenant,
isolate the Cardassians
in the foreground.
The one in profile on the left...
what can you give us?
That's him.
That's Marritza.
Not according to the caption.
What do you mean?
According to this,
it's Gul Darhe'el.
Let me guess.
You've come back to learn
the secret of my filing system.
I know all your secrets now.
Is that so?
What did you do?
Did you kill the real Marritza
so you could take his place?
Well, you'll pay for that death
and all the others
you're responsible for.
Oh, I don't think I could pay
for all of them, Major...
there were so many... and you
can only execute me once.
That's my only regret.
But... I'll settle for knowing
that Bajor will finally have
the satisfaction of punishing
the Butcher of Gallitep.
Tell me, Major.
Did you figure this out
all by yourself?
Or did you have help
from your Federation masters?
I'll let you
wonder about that.
It'll keep you occupied
while we're waiting
for the provisional government
to prepare
your war crimes tribunal.
War crimes?
How could there be war crimes
when there hasn't been a war?
I can understand your wish
that there had been a war.
Your need to indulge
some pathetic fantasy
about brave Bajoran soldiers
marching to honorable defeat.
But, in fact, Major
you and I know
there was no war, no glory.
Bajor didn't resist.
It surrendered.
The Bajorans were a peaceful
people before you came.
We offered no threat to you.
We could never understand
why you had to be so brutal.
Well, we can't have that, Major.
I want no more secrets
between us.
Anything you don't understand
I'll explain to you.
Thank you, but I think
I've heard enough of your lies.
What lies?
You mean my failure
to divulge my true identity?
Believe me, Major,
I yearned to tell you
but I knew how much more
satisfaction you would have
if you found out for yourself.
And that was my only deception.
Marritza was
a magnificent file clerk
and I, Gul Darhe'el...
I hope you'll not think it
immodest of me to say so...
but I was a magnificent leader.
Oh, you never saw Gallitep
at its height.
For a labor camp
it was the very model
of order and efficiency.
And why?
For that, you have
to look to the top.
To me!
My word,
my every glance was law
and the verdict
was always the same... guilty.
You're insane.
Oh, no, no, Major.
You can't dismiss me
that easily.
I did what had to be done.
My men understood that,
and that's why they loved me.
I would order them to go out
and kill Bajoran scum
and they'd do it,
they'd murder them
and they'd come back covered
in blood, but they felt clean.
Now, why did they feel
that way, Major?
Because they were clean.
You admit your atrocities.
I admit everything.
Why not?
I was the best at what I did.
My accomplishments
speak for themselves.
Can you say the same?
You and that little Shakaar
resistance cell
that you belonged to.
All you did was
annoy Cardassians
while I was out
exterminating Bajorans.
Make sure you tell that
to the tribunal.
Oh, I will.
Then they'll sentence you
to death.
Let them.
Don't you see, it doesn't
change anything?
Kill me, torture me...
it doesn't matter.
You've already lost, Major.
You can never undo
what I've accomplished.
The dead will still be dead.
What will you do now, Major?
Withhold my medicine?
Here.
This will help.
What is it?
Maraltian seev-ale
from Quark's private stock.
Better?
You know, Odo
I wonder how many others
like Darhe'el
are still out there...
still free, unpunished.
Quite a few, no doubt
but thanks to you,
there's one less out there now.
You should have heard him.
He bragged about
what happened at Gallitep...
the torture, the murders,
the humiliation.
He's proud
about what he did to us.
Why don't you go
to your quarters
and lie down for a while?
We'll leave him alone
with his Cardassian pride.
I don't want to lie down.
No, that's what he'd like...
another Bajoran
hiding in a corner.
He's probably in there
laughing at me right now.
He won't be laughing very long.
I hate him, Odo.
I hate his smirking,
superior Cardassian face.
When I was fighting
with the resistance
we used to lie awake at night
plotting the assassination
of men like Darhe'el.
Now I have to stand there
and listen to him
belittle the Shakaar
and everything it stood for.
Perhaps you should avoid
discussing your personal history
with a creature like that.
I didn't.
Then how did he know
you were with the Shakaar?
I don't know...
he was an important
military leader.
That doesn't explain it.
If he'd been in charge
of quelling Bajoran resistance
then he might have had
your name on file
but he commanded
a forced labor camp.
Something's not right here.
Where are you going?
To have another little chat
with Gul Darhe'el.
Computer, review
all off-station requests
for information regarding
Major Kira Nerys
within the last eight months.
Working.
Oh, back to see the Butcher.
Am I really so fascinating?
How did you know
I was with the Shakaar?
This provisional
government of yours
certainly moves slowly.
They should have dragged me
away in chains by now.
Just answer the question!
Oh, my, my, you are
a strutting little egotist.
You forget the brilliance
of Marritza's filing system.
He made sure that I was provided
with information
on all your little
terrorist bands.
What I particularly enjoyed
were the termination reports.
Yes, life in a forced labor camp
can be so isolating.
At times, I felt that I alone
bore the burden of cleansing
Bajor of its rabble
but those reports reassured me,
I was not alone.
And I'm supposed to believe
you remembered my name
from some report
you read years ago?
At the risk of bruising
your vanity even further, Major
I didn't remember you at all
until I heard your name here.
I can see that disturbs you.
Hardly.
You know, Major,
they will be coming for me soon
so before we say good-bye
there are a few little questions
I should like to ask you.
Your questions
don't interest me.
How can you be so sure?
Or are you just
afraid to hear them?
Who are they?
Survivors of Gallitep.
They arrived early this morning.
I suppose they are waiting
for justice.
Gallitep.
Imagine living
through that hellhole.
The pain...
the sorrow...
Do you think
they like to gamble?
Doctor, I need your help.
Of course.
Three months ago,
a request came from Kora II
for information
concerning Kira Nerys.
To what purpose?
I'm not sure.
But the name on the request
was Aamin Marritza.
I've established
a subspace link with Kora II
and I'd like you to access
his medical history there.
Dax to Odo.
Gul Dukat is responding
to your subspace transmission.
Could you route it
to my office?
Aye, sir.
I do miss working with you, Odo.
I miss our games
of Kalevian montar.
As I recall, Gul Dukat,
we played one game
and you cheated.
The same old Odo...
like a blunt instrument.
But now to your question.
I regret that I cannot give you
access to any of the files
pertaining to Gul Darhe'el.
But I assure you
the files would only tell you
what I am telling you.
Gul Darhe'el is dead.
That's not possible.
I attended his funeral myself.
As a matter of fact, he's buried
under one of the largest
military monuments on Cardassia.
Then who are we holding here?
Some innocent
Cardassian citizen
as I explained
to your Commander Sisko.
And we want him released.
That innocent citizen
has admitted he is Gul Darhe'el.
What... are you saying?
He says
his name is Gul Darhe'el.
Then he's lying.
Well, if he is,
it's the most foolish lie
he could have invented.
It's likely to get him executed.
Why would anyone
do such a thing?
I don't know
but I tell you
I attended Darhe'el's funeral.
You're sure the man
you saw buried was Gul Darhe'el?
Half of Cardassia
viewed his body.
I saw a photograph
of Gul Darhe'el
taken at the Gallitep
labor camp.
It certainly appears to be
the man we're holding.
You're mistaken.
Am I?
This is obviously some plot
to embarrass
the Cardassian Empire.
It's possible.
Give me access to your files
and perhaps I can find
some proof
to support your claim
that Gul Darhe'el is dead.
I suppose I could grant you
limited access to the files.
I think that's wise.
I was 12
when I started fighting
but I've heard of some
who were even younger than that.
Yes, yes,
let's get to the real issue!
How many Cardassians
did you kill?
I mean personally.
I didn't keep count.
Oh, I think you did.
And I'm sure your total
wasn't limited
to military personnel.
After all, the most effective
terrorist weapon
was random violence.
Don't leave now, Major.
It's just getting good.
How many Cardassian
civilians did you kill?
Look! I regret a lot
of what I had to do.
How convenient of you.
We had no choice!
We were fighting for survival.
So were we.
We had an Empire to protect.
We needed your resources.
Everything I did
was for the greater glory
of Cardassia!
And if you spineless scum
had to be ground under
so much the better.
All that mattered was Cardassia.
I loved my homeland.
That's what justified
my actions.
That's what gave me strength.
Nothing justifies genocide.
What you call genocide,
I call a day's work.
Major, could I have
a word with you?
Dr. Bashir and I have
done some checking.
I don't know why yet
but the man in that cell
wanted to be caught.
This certificate of death
was in the file sent
to me by Gul Dukat.
According to this, Gul Darhe'el
died in his sleep six years ago.
"Cause of death...
massive coleibric hemorrhage."
Commander, I guarantee you
that is a forged document.
I think it's pretty clear
what's going on here.
The Cardassians
are trying to trick us
into letting him go.
I wouldn't put it past
our friend Gul Dukat.
Nor would I, however...
The man in there confessed
he is Gul Darhe'el.
Major, the man in there
has Kalla-Nohra syndrome.
Of course he does.
According to the evidence
I've been sent
Gul Darhe'el
never contracted that condition.
More evidence
from our trustworthy Gul Dukat.
What have you got, Constable?
Darhe'el's progress reports
from Gallitep
show that, when
the mining accident occurred
he was back on Cardassia
being awarded the Proficient
Service Medallion.
If he wasn't at Gallitep
on the day on the accident
then he couldn't have contracted
Kalla-Nohra.
Correct.
But the man we're holding
does have it.
I can't believe
I'm listening to this.
I'm afraid there's more, Major.
I inquired about this man's
last two weeks on Kora II.
He resigned his position
at the military academy
put all his affairs in order
and even provided handsomely
for his housekeeper
I understand.
All right, all right.
So, like any criminal,
he wanted to move on
before somebody traced
his whereabouts.
He specifically
requested passage
on a vessel that was scheduled
to stop here...
at a Bajoran station.
Rather unusual request
for a Cardassian war criminal.
Unless he wanted to be captured.
Wait a minute.
Let's be clear about one thing.
This evidence may raise
some interesting questions.
Nevertheless, Darhe'el is going
to be sent back to Bajor
to stand trial
for the atrocities he committed.
Major, that is still
to be determined.
Well, then go talk to him.
If you still have any doubts,
listen to what he has to say.
He was there.
He did it.
He'll tell you about it.
Constable, I've checked
on Marritza's medical record.
What have we got?
He's under treatment
for Kalla-Nohra
syndrome, of course
and a few other minor ailments,
most relating to his age.
It's all pretty standard,
really, except for one thing.
Which is?
Five years ago,
after arriving on Kora II
he started taking massive doses
of dermatiraelian plastiscine
which is a dermal
regenerative agent
used to maintain
skin resilience
after cosmetic alteration.
You're saying
he changed his face
to look like Gul Darhe'el.
It certainly appears that way.
How are you feeling?
I was starting to get
a little bored
but seeing you again
brightens my day.
I was referring
to your Kalla-Nohra Syndrome.
Would you like to see
Dr. Bashir?
Oh, so that's it.
You want to see me writhing
around the floor in pain.
A Cardassian would never put on
such a deplorable display
in front of a Bajoran.
You just don't
understand us at all.
I'm beginning to understand
a great deal about you.
One thing does puzzle me.
And what would that be?
How you contracted
Kalla-Nohra Syndrome.
Do you think
that the mining accident
affected only
the Bajoran laborers
and not
their Cardassian masters?
That would be very nice.
So you're saying
you were at Gallitep
when that mining accident
occurred.
Of course.
Why are we going over
this again?
Because your own progress report
shows you were back on Cardassia
at the time of the accident.
That's ridiculous.
Receiving your
Proficient Service Medallion.
The reports are wrong.
I can show them to you.
That won't be necessary.
I know where I was.
Why were you taking
a dermal regenerative?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Then let me help you.
Five years ago,
when you first got to Kora II...
All right, that's enough!
Your presence no longer
amuses me. Get out!
Why did you have
your face altered?
Security, get this woman
out of here!
Why are you pretending
to be Gul Darhe'el?
Why don't you ask me
something intelligent?!
As for instance, how did I feel
when we were withdrawing
from Bajor?
The answer is I was furious.
The thought of leaving
any survivors behind
was repulsive to me.
So while our useless
office clerks
were packing
their precious files
I ordered my overseers
to begin slaughtering
the laborers.
If you felt that way
about your filing clerks
why did you take
Marritza's name?
My plan was to do nothing less
than kill every Bajoran
in the camp
and, to this day, my one regret
is that I was not able
to accomplish
this honorable goal.
You're Marritza, aren't you?
You mistake me for that bug?
That whimpering nothing?
Oh, you stupid Bajoran girl.
Don't you know who I am?
I'm your nemesis.
I'm your nightmare.
I'm the Butcher of Gallitep.
The Butcher of Gallitep
died six years ago.
You're Aamin Marritza,
his filing clerk.
That's not true.
I am alive.
I will always be alive!
It's Marritza who is dead.
Marritza,
who was good for nothing
but cowering under his bunk
and weeping like a woman.
Who, every night,
covered his ears
because he couldn't bear to hear
the screaming for mercy
of the Bajorans.
Covered my ears every night,
but...
I couldn't bear to hear
those horrible screams.
You have no idea
what it's like to be a coward...
to see these horrors...
and do nothing.
Marritza's dead.
He deserves to be dead.
What are you doing?
I'm letting you go.
Security?
Get in here.
You didn't commit those crimes
and you couldn't stop them.
You were only one man.
No, no, don't you see?
I have to be punished.
We all have to be punished.
Major, you have
to go out and tell them
I'm Gul Darhe'el.
It's the only way.
Why are you doing this?
For Cardassia.
Cardassia will only survive
if it stands in front of Bajor
and admits the truth.
My trial will force Cardassia
to acknowledge its guilt
and we're guilty, all of us.
My death is necessary.
What you're asking for
is another murder.
Enough good people
have already died.
I won't help kill another.
You should be back on Kora II
in three days.
Well, there's nothing
for me to go back to.
We've contacted officials there.
They'll be waiting to help you.
If they believed
that I was Gul Darhe'el
then my trial might have helped
to bring about a new Cardassia.
Now you've told them
I was just a file clerk.
What you tried to do
was very honorable.
If Cardassia is going to change
it's going to need
people like you.
Why?!
He wasn't Darhe'el!
He's a Cardassian!
That's reason enough.
No!
It's not.