O'BRIEN: Try one.
You'll like it.
Too early for me.
You sure?
It's so sweet.
It's a natural sweetness
from the sap
of the jumja tree.
It's full
of vitamin C.
Since when did you
become such an expert
on jumja sticks?
Oh, Neela told me.
Did she?
Mm-hmm.
So...
she working out any better
than the last one?
Who, Neela?
She's terrific.
She's even taught me
a thing or two.
I'm glad to hear
her expertise
doesn't end with
jumja sticks.
No. She's
a really good engi...
Hold on.
What?
Well...
you're not thinking...?
Well, Keiko!
Just keeping you
on your toes, O'Brien.
Oh, very funny.
Be careful
who you share
your jumja with.
KEIKO:
Now, as we discussed
in yesterday's lesson
the wormhole was discovered
by Commander Sisko
and Lieutenant Dax
earlier this year.
Does anyone know
what makes this wormhole
so unusual?
Jake?
It's stable?
It's stable.
That's right, Jake.
It's the first stable wormhole
known to exist...
Please, continue.
A stable wormhole
is very important
because it allows us to travel,
secure in the knowledge
that neither end
will shift locations.
Who knows why this wormhole
is stable?
Because it was
artificially constructed.
Commander Sisko
encountered the entities
who created the wormhole
when he went...
Excuse me.
By entities,
do you not mean the Prophets?
Yes, on Bajor, the entities
are worshipped as Prophets.
Our studies of
the wormhole have shown
that it was formed
by unique particles
we call "verterons"
that are apparently
self-sustaining in nature.
This begins to explain
how a ship at impulse can safely
pass through without...
Ships are safely
guided through
the passage
by the hands
of the Prophets.
In a manner of speaking.
Not, apparently,
in your manner
of speaking.
Perhaps we should discuss this
after class.
Do you believe
the Celestial Temple
of the Prophets
exists within the passage?
I respect
that the Bajoran people
believe that it does.
But that's not what you teach.
No. I don't teach
Bajoran spiritual beliefs.
That's your job.
Mine is to open
the children's minds to...
history, to literature,
to mathematics, to science.
You are opening
the children's minds--
to blasphemy,
and I cannot permit it
to continue.
Sorry I couldn't
get here sooner.
Another fusion reactor
went down.
How's it going?
Done.
Done?
Did you remember to
re-initialize the isolinear
coprocessor?
I did it exactly
like you showed me.
Should I test it?
Well, uh, let me.
You know us old folks.
We like to feel useful.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
You keep this up,
I'll be out of a job.
I doubt that.
Let's close it up.
Not that one.
That's a security seal.
You need an
EJ7 interlock
to close it.
EJ7?
Yeah. That's okay.
I have one here.
Bloody hell.
What's wrong?
Well, my EJ7 is missing.
It was here yesterday.
Maybe you left it
in Ops.
No. I...
I don't misplace
my tools.
I'm not exactly surprised.
You knew this was
going to happen?
A confrontation like this
was inevitable.
Sometimes I wonder
if we'll ever find
the common ground we need
to bring Bajor
into the Federation.
Major, would you join us?
We've been talking
about an incident
this morning at school.
I heard.
Vedek Winn's been meeting
with some of the Bajoran
civilians about it.
What do you know about her?
She's from an
orthodox order.
She has some support
to become the next Kai...
probably not enough.
The question is,
how much support
does she have
on this station?
She has mine.
KEIKO:
You can't possibly believe
teaching the facts
about the wormhole
amounts to blasphemy.
I think some revisions
in the school curriculum
might be appropriate.
You teach a lot
of Bajoran children.
I'm not going to let
a Bajoran spiritual leader
dictate what can
or can't be taught
in my classroom.
Then maybe we need
two schools
on this station--
one for the
Bajoran children
and another for
the Federation.
If we start separating Bajoran
and Federation interests...
A lot of Bajoran and
Federation interests
are separate,
Commander.
I've been telling
you that all along.
Nobody's saying
that there can't be
spiritual teaching
on the station, Major,
but can't it be
in addition to what's taught
in Mrs. O'Brien's classroom?
But if she's teaching
a fundamentally
different philosophy...
I'm not teaching
any philosophy.
What I'm trying to teach
is pure science.
Some might say
pure science
taught without a
spiritual context
is a philosophy,
Mrs. O'Brien.
My philosophy is
that there is room
for all philosophies
on this station.
Now, how do you suggest
that we deal with this?
I'm not sure
you can.
I can't tell you how much
I've looked forward
to this moment.
I'm honored to meet
the Emissary to the Prophets.
If you'd let me know you
were coming, Vedek Winn,
I would have
greeted you sooner.
I did not wish to bother you
with my insignificant visit.
I'd hardly call it
insignificant.
Thank you, Emissary.
I wish you wouldn't
call me that.
I'm Commander Sisko,
or Benjamin, if you like.
But you are the Emissary.
Don't you know
the cherished place
you have earned
in the Bajoran spiritual life?
I'm not sure
I'm comfortable
in that role.
The course the Prophets
choose for us
may not always be comfortable
but we must follow it.
May I?
Still the disbeliever.
I once asked Kai Opaka
why a disbeliever was destined
to seek the Prophets
and she told me that one
must never look into the eyes
of one's own gods.
I disagreed.
I told her I would do anything
to look into their eyes.
She suggested that I sit
in darkness for a day,
and quite properly so.
She cannot be replaced,
and I miss her deeply.
It's important to me
that we resolve your problems
with the school.
The Prophets have spoken to me
through the Orbs, Emissary.
I understand my duty
to defend the Bajoran faith.
The teacher has dishonored
the Celestial Temple.
If she does not recant,
I cannot be responsible
for the consequences.
This still seems like
an awful lot of trouble
to go through
to find one tool.
With that interlock,
someone could access
every critical system
on the station.
DAX:
Chief, have you seen
Ensign Aquino recently?
No, now that
you mention it.
He didn't report for duty
this morning.
The computer says
he's not on the station,
but he didn't log out.
Have you
talked to Odo?
I guess I'd better.
Scanners are ready.
Computer, show location
of any independent
tritanium sources.
Level 3, Section 5.
Oh, that's the tool locker.
I've been through everything
in there three times.
What's that?
Looks like something
in a power conduit
on Level 12, Section 8.
What would tritanium
be doing there?
Computer, shut down
that conduit.
Reroute power flow.
Conduit deactivated.
Come on.
Over here, Chief.
That's tritanium
composite, all right.
Looks like our
missing interlock.
Must have been melted
by the conduit's plasma flow.
That still doesn't
explain how it got here
in the first place.
( tricorder beeping )
Hey...
I'm picking up traces
of organic material.
Whatever it was,
it's been pretty
well cooked.
Let's take a sample
to Dr. Bashir.
See what he can make of it.
Ensign Aquino made a
log entry the night
he disappeared
about some sort of plasma flow
irregularity in the conduit.
He indicated he was
going to fix it.
So, it was an accident.
Well, I guess so.
Bashir has confirmed that
the remains were human.
I'm sure the DNA trace
will confirm that
it was Aquino.
I'll have one, please...
unless you're feeling
adventurous today.
Sorry. We're all out.
What?
What are all these?
These aren't for sale.
Not for sale, huh?
How would you like
a jumja stick up...?
Miles.
ODO:
Is there a problem?
Damn right
there is!
I don't have to sell
anything to them
if I don't want to.
Why wouldn't you want
to sell to them?
Miles, can we go?
Let's go.
Seek the Prophets.
I'll seek you...
Miles!
Seek them yourself.
Maybe you were right.
Maybe we've no
business here.
I'll put in for a
transfer, and that'll...
No, I can't run away
from this now.
WINN:
...don't you
all agree?
What's this?
WINN:
If we abandon
the Prophets,
then everything we have...
Here's Mrs. O'Brien now.
Good morning.
WINN:
Are you Mr. O'Brien?
That's right.
A pleasure to meet you.
I've just been hearing
many wonderful things
about your wife
from the parents
of these children.
She apparently is
an excellent teacher.
Yes, she is,
and she doesn't deserve
what you're doing to her.
WINN:
I feel your anger toward me
and I forgive you for it.
Mrs. O'Brien,
if I've misjudged you,
I am terribly sorry.
Have I?
Is there a place in your school
for the Prophets?
No.
I admire you for
standing by your convictions
even though I disagree
with them.
Please believe me,
I want to find a way
to allow these children
to stay in your school.
I'm sure the children
and their parents
are happy
to hear you say that.
Let me be the one
to make the first concession.
I will no longer request
that you teach anything
about the Celestial Temple.
Just don't teach anything
about the wormhole at all.
Ignore it?
Find other ways,
other things
to teach the children.
And when we get
to theories of evolution
or creation of the universe--
what then?
We'll face those issues
when we come to them.
I'm a teacher.
My responsibility
is to expose my students
to knowledge,
not hide it from them.
The answer is no.
( murmuring voices )
I've tried to be reasonable.
SISKO:
If Aquino turned off the conduit
to fix the relay,
why did it reactivate?
The Cardassians only equipped
those power conduits
with one flow regulator
per level.
The computer
could have realigned it.
When the power flow
was rerouted back
it could have caught
him inside.
You don't sound
entirely convinced.
No, it all adds up, only...
Well, I don't know.
Spit it out, Chief.
He borrowed one of my tools
without asking.
It was 4:00 in the morning.
Maybe he didn't want
to disturb you.
The repairs
could have waited.
He was a Starfleet engineer.
You don't take a Chief's
tools without asking.
It's unheard of.
Are you suggesting
it might not have
been an accident?
I don't know what
I'm suggesting.
I only know what I know.
He should have asked.
Constable, maybe you ought
to take a closer look into this.
Dismissed.
Hi.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Sure.
I heard about what happened
at school.
Did Mrs. O'Brien
call classes off?
No, there was only me
and four other kids left
but she still kept
the school open.
She changed the lesson
to teach us
about Galileo.
Did you know that he was
tried by the Inquisition
for teaching that the Earth
moved around the sun?
Tried and convicted.
His books were burned.
How could anyone
be so stupid?
It's easy to look back
seven centuries
and judge what was
right and wrong.
But the same thing
is happening now
with all this stuff
about the Celestial Temple
and the wormhole.
It's dumb.
No, it's not.
You've got to realize
something, Jake.
For over 50 years, the one thing
that allowed the Bajorans
to survive
the Cardassian occupation
was their faith.
The Prophets
were their only source
of hope and courage.
But there were no Prophets.
They were just aliens that
you found in the wormhole.
To those aliens,
the future is no more
difficult to see
than the past.
Why shouldn't they be
considered Prophets?
Are you serious?
My point is, it's a matter
of interpretation.
It may not be what you believe,
but that doesn't make it wrong.
If you start
to think that way,
you'll be acting
just like Vedek Winn.
Only from the other side.
We can't afford
to think that way, Jake.
We'd lose everything
we've worked for here.
You're worried,
aren't you?
What are you
going to do?
I'm not sure,
but I think I've got
to find some help.
I'm sorry to keep you
waiting, Commander.
Vedek Bareil?
No need to pay
tribute to me.
Pay tribute?
I was just...
Usually when I meet
one of Bajor's spiritual leaders
the first thing they do
is grab my...
Ear?
It's unpleasant,
isn't it?
I've been far too polite
to admit it.
I was five the first time one
of the monks grabbed my ear.
He was a stern old crow
who could virtually squeeze
the pagh out of you
with his thumb and forefinger.
And as a chronic
misbehaver,
I was his
favorite victim.
I swore one of
my life's goals
would be to do away
with that archaic ritual.
You can count
on the Federation's support.
( chuckling )
I hope you don't mind
if I do a little planting
while we talk.
All those hours
of listening
to 112 vedeks
talking at once
made me yearn
for the sanctity
of my arboretum.
Is this yours?
I began my service at the
monastery as the gardener.
I had no other
ambition but to grow
the most lovely Feloran
bromeliads on the planet.
Unfortunately,
the Prophets
did not allow me
that peaceful life.
I understand my friend
Vedek Winn
has brought her blessings
to your station.
I was hoping you might be able
to arrange an audience
with the Assembly
so I could discuss
our school.
Why me?
You are the leading
candidate to become
the next Kai.
Your ideology
is quite different
than Vedek Winn's.
You have been correctly
informed.
I'm sorry, Commander.
The Vedek Assembly
will not see you.
Why not?
Some fear you as the symbol
of a Federation
they view as godless.
Some fear you as the Emissary
who walked with the Prophets.
And some fear you because
Vedek Winn told them to.
Oh, we're all very good
at conjuring up enough fear
to justify whatever
we want to do.
Today, I am only a vedek.
If the Prophets will it,
someday I may be Kai
and I can be a better friend
to you then.
In other words,
being my friend now
might hurt your chances.
The Prophets teach us patience.
It appears they also
teach you politics.
I'm sorry you made
this long trip
for nothing, Commander.
Please stay
and enjoy the gardens
as long as you like.
Is it my imagination
or are we a little
shorthanded today?
Three Bajoran crewmen
didn't report for duty.
They said
they weren't feeling well.
Do you think
it's contagious, Major?
It's too early to tell.
Are your people willing
to throw away
everything we've accomplished
during the past seven months?
Everyone knows if
the Federation leaves
the Cardassians
will be back.
With all due respect,
Major,
protecting your borders
is not the primary reason
the Federation is here,
and it's not why I'm here.
I'm here to build a trusting
relationship with your people
and I'd like to start feeling
that somebody...
somebody on your side
is giving something back
to that effort.
I think I've given
you all the support
I can, short of...
It's not enough.
I thought there
was room
for all philosophies
on this station.
You tell
our sick Bajoran crewmen
they better get well
immediately
or they'll recover on the way
to their next assignment.
Yes, sir.
Commander, Dr. Bashir has found
some new evidence
about Ensign Aquino
that you should see.
Sir, I've finally
managed to reconstruct
the victim's DNA.
It's definitely Aquino,
but the power flow
in the conduit
didn't kill him.
You see, the plasma
disruption in his
cellular membranes
indicates that
he was exposed
to a directed
energy discharge
before he was
placed in the conduit.
O'BRIEN:
A directed energy discharge?
From a phaser?
Set to kill.
Could this murder be related
in any way
to the tensions
over the school issue?
If you're suggesting
he was killed by a Bajoran
just because
he was with
the Federation...
The analysis proves
that he was killed
the night before
Vedek Winn arrived.
There wasn't
any school issue yet.
Any ideas about a motive?
All right, then let's
start at the beginning.
Ensign Aquino goes
to repair a power conduit.
One moment, Commander.
I'm not convinced of that.
But the log...
It could have been altered
by our killer
to cover his tracks.
I've checked the turbolift
records the night of the murder.
Aquino did take
a turbolift to Level 3,
but not to the power conduit
where he was found.
DAX:
Where did he go?
ODO:
Runabout Pad C.
A runabout?
What was he doing
in a runabout at
4:00 in the morning?
Apparently, he was
getting murdered.
Everything in the runabout
seems to be perfectly normal.
It doesn't look
like the airlock systems
have been tampered with.
Let's run a
level-1 diagnostic
on the runabout's
computer interface--
then we'll call it a day.
I already have.
Everything's normal.
I don't even know
what we're looking for.
If something
happened around here,
it's been pretty
well covered up.
Did you know him well?
Aquino?
Oh, barely at all.
Just the
"welcome aboard
if you need
anything" speech.
You?
Not really.
Bajoran
and Starfleet officers
don't really socialize
that much.
How come?
I don't know.
I guess we just
keep to ourselves.
Well, you're not
like that with me.
like the others.
You know.
You don't put on
any airs.
You're just...
nicer.
Uh, look...
I'll close up here.
Why don't you take off.
You sure?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Good night.
On your toes, O'Brien.
You were looking for me?
Don't tell me--
there's a Bajoran convention
on the station
I didn't know about.
Thanks, Odo.
I need to call in
more dabo girls.
It's not a convention.
They're from an
orthodox spiritual order
coming to support
Vedek Winn's efforts
to keep the Bajoran
children out of school.
Orthodox?
In that case,
I'll need twice as many
dabo girls.
These spiritual types
love those dabo girls.
This is not what I wanted
to talk to you about.
What do you know
about the murder
of Ensign Aquino?
You wound me.
All these years together,
I thought you knew me.
Odo, I am not a killer.
No, but most of
your friends are.
True, and I would
gladly sell one of them
to you if I could,
but unfortunately,
none of them have taken credit
for the death
of the Starfleet officer.
Sorry.
O'BRIEN:
Odo!
Keep your ears open.
Are you kidding?
That's the Seventh Rule
of Acquisition.
This is
a security bypass module.
You found it at
Runabout Pad C?
No, that's just it.
It wasn't at Pad C.
That was as clean
as a whistle.
Just to be safe,
I ran a diagnostic
across the board.
This showed up
at Runabout Pad A.
Pad A...
Aquino never went
anywhere near Pad A.
It doesn't make sense.
On the contrary,
it makes perfect sense.
Ensign Aquino goes
to Runabout C
because some sensor
shows an anomaly
in the security net there.
He interrupts whoever
is tampering with it
and is killed.
The killer puts the
body in the conduit
and instead of going
back to Pad C,
which might be traced with
Aquino's turbolift log,
he changes his plan
and moves to Pad A.
But what was the plan?
Everything else seems normal.
I'd guess somebody wanted
to steal a runabout.
We're not missing one.
Huh. It's curious.
He goes to a lot
of trouble
to defeat
the security net
and then doesn't
go through with...
( explosion )
The school!
( alarm blaring )
( screams
and exclamations )
Keiko!
Miles!
FIREMAN:
Stand back, please!
Clear the way!
What have you got?
I'm reading traces
of cabrodine and infernite--
common explosives,
both easily obtainable.
Then we're looking
at a simple, homemade bomb.
( crowd clamoring )
Where is Mrs. O'Brien?
Her husband
took her home.
Was she hurt?
Was anyone hurt?
No.
The Prophets have
been kind today.
The Prophets had
nothing to do with what
happened here today.
This was the work
of a disturbed
and violent mind
who listened
to your voice,
not the Prophets'.
Is the Emissary
holding me responsible
for this act of terrorism?
The Commander of
this station is.
May the Prophets forgive you
for abandoning them.
You claim the Prophets
as your personal
constituency, Vedek Winn.
I'm not convinced
that's justified.
Who do you speak for?
An order that's barely
listened to in your Assembly.
So you come here looking
for a more receptive audience.
Is that what your friend,
Vedek Bareil, told you?
He's as misguided
as you are.
No, that's not fair.
You are not simply misguided,
as I once thought.
Now I see you want nothing less
than to destroy us.
Destroy you?
You live without a soul,
Commander.
You and your Federation exist
in a universe of darkness
and you would drag us
in there with you.
But we will not go.
You have just made your
first mistake, Vedek.
Have I?
The Bajorans who have lived
with us on this station,
who have worked
with us for months,
who helped us move this station
to protect the wormhole,
who joined us to explore
the Gamma Quadrant,
who have begun to
build the future
of Bajor with us,
these people know
that we are neither
the enemy nor the devil.
( murmurs of agreement )
We don't always agree.
We have some damn
good fights, in fact,
but we always come
away from them
with a little better
understanding
and appreciation
of each other.
You won't succeed here.
The school will reopen.
And when your
rhetoric gets old,
the Bajoran parents
will bring their children back.
We'll see.
( crowd murmuring )
How is she, Chief?
She's pretty
shaken up, sir,
but she's planning to
hold classes tomorrow
in one of the
small cargo bays,
if that's okay.
You tell her Jake
will be there on time.
It will make her
feel a lot better
to hear that, sir.
Anything new on Aquino?
Yes, sir.
I found a security
bypass module
at Runabout Pad A.
It looks like somebody
might have wanted
to steal a runabout.
That's probably why
Aquino went there
in the first place.
I've put security seals
in place at all three pads
and I'm checking for
any other anomalies.
DAX:
Benjamin, there's an incoming
transmission from Vedek Bareil
on board a Bajoran transport.
On screen.
Commander, I've decided
to accept
your gracious invitation.
Invitation?
You did invite me
to tour your facility.
Yes, yes, of course, Vedek.
We'd be honored.
Unfortunately, we have
some damage on our Promenade.
We won't have time to clean up
before you arrive.
Yes, I heard about it.
Perhaps I can help you
clean it up.
That would be very
much appreciated.
It's the least a friend can do.
I look forward
to seeing you again.
My dear,
you should not be here.
Vedek, they found out
about the runabout.
I see.
I have no way to escape.
Then we must accept that
as the will of the Prophets.
But if I go through
with this now,
I will be caught
and executed.
The sacrifices the Prophets
call on us to make
are great sometimes,
my dear,
but the rewards they give
will last through eternity.
What the hell?
Computer, identify subprogram
labeled "ANA".
That file is protected
by a personal
security access code.
On whose authority?
Chief of Operations,
Miles O'Brien.
Me? I never saw
this file before.
Override command.
Unable to comply.
State security code
to release protection.
Lieutenant, I've got to do
a manual isolation
of an anomalous file.
It's in the security field
subsystem labeled "ANA".
That file is going to be
protected by a series
of encryption sequences.
I'll run an adaptive program.
For once, we're lucky
we're working with
a Cardassian computer.
It shouldn't have any more
than seven sequences.
Beginning decryption.
On-line.
Patched to subprogram ANA.
( clamoring )
Clear the way.
Make room.
Move along, now.
Clear the way.
Clear the way, now.
Please stand back.
Clear the way, please.
Thank you.
( clamoring continues )
That's it.
Computer, access
subprogram ANA.
Code 4100RLX.
Accessing.
Identify commands
within the file.
Commands are
sequential overrides
of security fields
approaching Runabout Pad A.
The force fields.
Display sequences on screen.
Right to the Promenade.
Computer, run a level-3
sensor sweep of the Promenade.
Report any anomalous reading.
Working.
An escape route.
Escape from what?
You got me.
One anomalous reading detected.
Identify.
A subspace relay was activated
in the security office
nine minutes, seven seconds ago.
Activated to do what?
Unknown.
Insufficient data.
I'm going down there.
I'll run a diagnostic on
the other security systems
and I'll call you as soon
as I have anything.
Promenade.
I expected you
sooner, Bareil.
It seems our paths
have grown apart.
Perhaps we can
bring them together again.
I would like nothing
better than that.
Come with me to the school.
Let us both show
our commitment
to a peaceful resolution
to this series of events.
Of course.
( tricorder whirring )
( beeping )
Computer, is the subspace
device integrated
into the isolinear coprocessor?
Confirmed.
( sighing )
O'Brien to Dax.
Go ahead.
It's in
the isolinear coprocessor.
Didn't you just repair
that unit two days ago?
Yes, I did.
With Neela.
Looking around
at your faces,
I believe you feel
the shame I feel
at this sight.
No, it's got to be
the weapon detectors
in the Promenade.
That's the only thing
those coprocessors
could possibly affect.
All weapon detectors appear
to be functional, Chief.
That's got to be it.
She's good.
She's real good.
She could make it look
like they're normal.
But it's got to be
the weapon detectors.
O'Brien to Sisko.
BAREIL:
Once, our world was
a center of learning.
It attracted travelers
from many other worlds.
Go ahead, Chief.
I'm not entirely sure, but...
I think the weapon detectors
on the Promenade
may have been disabled.
What do you mean,
you're not sure?
I mean Neela
may have disabled them.
Your assistant?
Yes, sir.
...to reject violence
as a solution,
to join hands
with all peoples
and begin to trust again.
( crowd cheers )
No!
( crowd yelling )
The Prophets spoke.
I answered their call.
The Prophets spoke!
I answered their call!
It was all
to get him here, wasn't it?
The school, the protest,
the bombing--
you knew that would get him
out of the monastery.
You did it all to kill him--
to stop him
from becoming Kai.
Neela insists
she acted alone--
unless you want to consider
the Prophets coconspirators.
She'll never
tell us the truth.
We'll never be able to prove
that Winn was involved.
You okay?
Okay?
I've forgotten "okay."
I haven't seen "okay"
in what seems like years.
I was just sitting here
thinking,
last year at this time
I was fighting the Cardassians
in some nameless swamp.
And if you'd stopped by
and told me
that just one year later,
they'd be gone,
and I'd be wearing
this uniform,
up here in charge
of protecting some wormhole...
Protecting your
Celestial Temple.
I envied Vedek Winn
because she was
a true believer.
I wanted my faith
to be as strong as hers.
Maybe it is.
I've got a report
to put together
for Starfleet.
You ought to
get some rest.
I'd rather help you.
Commander...
I heard what you said to
Vedek Winn at the school.
I just wanted
you to know...
you were right--
what you said
about the Bajorans--
at least about me.
I don't think
that you're...
the devil.
Maybe we have made
some progress after all.