ANNOUNCER:
Last time on
Deep Space Nine...
SISKO: This is the emblem
of  the Alliance
for Global Unity.
They call themselves
the Circle.
What gives them the right
to mess up our station?
They're an extremist faction
who believe in Bajor
for the Bajorans.
I can't loan you
a Starfleet runabout
without knowing
where you plan on taking it.
To Cardassia IV
to rescue
a Bajoran prisoner of war.
( grunts )
Come on, we have
a ship waiting.
What if I told you
that I knew someone
who could bring stability
to Bajor?
Someone who could
unite the factions
and give us a chance
to do our job.
But Bajor doesn't
need a man.
It needs a symbol
and that's
what you are.
The Navarch needed to return
here to assume his new post.
He's been made the Bajoran
Liaison Officer
to Deep Space 9.
I already have
a Liaison Officer.
Not anymore,
you don't.
Major Kira is no longer
assigned to this post.
She's been recalled to Bajor.
QUARK:
It's over,
everything.
Bajor, the provisional
government
the Federation being
here-- all of it.
We gotta leave.
The provisional government
will stand only if the military
supports it.
We are all patriots, Commander.
I am the Circle, Major.
How can you
betray your own government?
The Circle's being supplied
by the Cardassians.
What?
I... borrowed the proof.
It's got a gul's thumb scan
on it.
The Circle hates
the Cardassians.
They don't know
it is the Cardassians.
They think
they've been buying
from Kressari traders.
Think of the prestige of having
the new leader of Bajor
being a member of your order.
If you are the new leader.
Commander, two assault
vessels are headed this way
on direct course
from Bajor.
They've given
all non-Bajorans
seven hours to evacuate.
ANNOUNCER:
And now, the conclusion.
Starfleet feels it has
no other choice.
The Federation is here
at the invitation
of the Bajoran
provisional government.
No more provisional government,
no more invitation.
Governments can break off
relations with an edict.
It's not so easy
when it comes down
to our level, hmm?
Lieutenant Bilecki here
is engaged to a young
man from Bajor.
Ensign Kelly.
Ensign Kelly's daughter
worked together
with a young Bajoran girl
on a prize-winning
science fair project.
All of us who have served
on the station for
the past year
have made Bajoran friends.
We've come to care about
what happens to these people.
I know I do.
So I've decided to stay.
( muttering )
Just to make sure
the evacuation
is conducted properly.
You'll need someone
to oversee the
inventory process, sir.
Packing away
all my medical supplies
could take, uh, quite
a while, Commander.
( mutters of support )
Before you volunteer
too quickly
understand
what you're getting into.
We'll be trying to delay
the takeover of the station
as long as possible.
Hopefully, as long as it takes
to expose the Cardassians'
involvement in all of this.
It won't be easy.
The Bajoran assault forces
have been told
that the Federation
is their blood enemy.
Jaro and the Circle
would love nothing more
than to have my head,
and yours
and present them
to the Chamber of Ministers.
This is your last chance
to leave here in one piece.
Some of you have families.
Some are
on temporary assignment.
I wouldn't blame anyone
for getting out now
while you can.
I mean that.
Anyone who wants to evacuate
is dismissed.
Non-Bajorans
won't be safe here.
Our families, children,
have to be evacuated.
I'm sure many of the Bajorans
who have worked with us
will want to leave, too.
There is a lot to get done.
The assault vessels
will be here
in less than five hours.
Dismissed.
( buzz of conversation )
Hundreds of people
to evacuate
and only three tiny
runabouts available.
Do you know
what that means?
It... it means...
Well, a lot of people
will be left behind.
Tragic. Yes, brother.
Your compassion
never ceases to amaze me.
It means we're going
to make a fortune.
We are?
People will pay anything
for a seat on those ships.
You can't make me...
Well, I won't
sell my seat.
Rom.
No! I won't stay
and be killed
just to fill your pockets.
Rom, do you
actually believe
that I would sacrifice
my own brother's life...
for personal profit?
It would have to be
the deal of a lifetime.
Yes, my lifetime.
Listen to me.
We're both
going to escape...
but our bags
will be filled
with all the gold-pressed
latinum we can carry.
Nog!
I've been looking
all over for you.
What ship you on?
Rio Grande.
I'm on the Ganges.
Oh. Well, it'll be okay.
We'll see each other
at the Hanolan colony
in a few days.
That's not where I'm going.
But my dad told me...
My ship's going
to the Korat system.
I guess that's
where they're taking
all the Starfleet families.
Well, this will be
over in no time.
We'll be back in school
driving Mrs. O'Brien crazy
in a few days.
Just when I think
I've found a new home
and a new friend
it always seems
like I got to leave.
Hey, hu-man...
Cut it out!
Has there ever been
one of your kind
and one of my kind
who were better friends?
Never.
And if our fathers
couldn't break us up
no stupid coupe day... coupe...
Coup d'état.
It's French.
Well, no stupid
French thing will, either.
We'll see each other
again soon.
That's a promise.
Mr. Sisko, Nog--
this is no time
to be fooling about.
Get yourselves to wherever
you're supposed to be.
Is that everything?
Sure.
Oh, Keiko, please.
Don't go like this.
Like what?
I don't have any choice.
Don't you?
He needs me.
We don't?
We can't just let the Cardies
have the wormhole.
They could have the
whole Gamma Quadrant
for all I care.
Miles...
come with us.
Where are we going?
On a ride, sweetheart.
Are you coming,
too, Daddy?
Soon, baby.
I'll come as
soon as I can.
I'll walk you to the airlock.
DAX:
I've scanned every subspace
communication window
to find
a frequency to Bajor.
They've got them
completely jammed.
Then we have no choice.
We'll have to take the proof
to the Chamber of Ministers.
Jaro's forces
will be scanning
for any incoming vessels.
A runabout could handle
a Bajoran patrol.
Unfortunately,
I don't have one to give you.
The Lunar V base?
You think there's still
a ship there?
We managed to get
a few subimpulse raiders
underground
before the Cardassians hit us,
but that was ten years ago.
Could one
of the evacuation vessels
take a detour and drop me off?
What if you get there
and those raiders won't fly?
Then I'll have to wait
until I hear from you, I guess.
You may have to wait
a long time.
Dax...
do any of your former
hosts have experience
with subimpulse
thruster configurations?
Yes. Tobin Dax.
Tobin? I don't think
I've heard about this one.
My second host.
Barely a sex life,
and no imagination
but he knew phase
coil inverters
like no one else.
Major Kira could use
his experience today.
I have no time
for this foolishness.
I still have to pack.
SISKO:
What's the problem?
He's been brokering seats
on the evacuation vessels.
Where did you
get more seats?
Everybody always
asks the brokers
where they get
their extra seats.
And all I can say
is it's my business
to find preferred seating
for a select list of clients...
I have got more
than 200 people
who want to get
off this station.
Where did you
get more seats?!
A few trades.
A person here or there
who changed his mind
about leaving
at the sight
of a reasonable stipend.
BASHIR:
Bashir to Commander Sisko.
Go ahead.
We're having a bit of a panic
at the airlock, sir.
Far more passengers than
we can handle have shown up
and they all claim to have
made arrangements to leave.
I might have overbooked,
slightly.
On my way.
It's an accepted
Ferengi transit practice.
I feel perfectly justified.
I have complete faith
in Commander Sisko's ability
to straighten this out.
I'll pass that on.
He'll be so pleased to know
that he has your confidence.
As I'm no longer needed
my brother is waiting for
me on the ship.
( scoffs )
Hey, Odo.
You'll miss me.
You know you will.
Say it.
I'll miss you, Quark.
You said it!
I'll miss the aggravation
the petty theft,
the bad manners...
Odo... take care of yourself.
( laughing )
( shouting )
Don't you understand?!
There isn't room for everyone.
We have to get our families,
our children
and non-Bajorans...
Where are you running to?!
This is Bajor.
We are Bajorans.
We fought a war
to regain our homeland.
How can you abandon it
like frightened Cardassian
vole?
These ships
are for our guests
who must leave
because it is no longer safe
for them here.
However, we are Bajorans...
and I say that we stay
and we solve our own problems.
Together.
Are you willing to join me?
( murmurs of agreement )
As soon as the passenger lists
are confirmed
get these ships
out of here.
They're almost ready to go,
sir.
The Rio Grande is full
and so is the Orinoco.
Get them launched.
Aye, sir.
Are you ready?
I've been thinking.
I really think it'd
be better if I stayed.
( chuckles )
Look, I just don't want
anything to happen to you.
That makes two of us.
What's this?
A letter I wrote you.
A letter?
Just some things.
I'll read it as soon
as I get on the ship.
Wait a while.
I'll see you in
a couple of weeks.
That's everyone, sir.
Sisko to Ganges.
Proceed with launch.
KIRA:
Acknowledged.
Good luck, Commander.
Kira out.
QUARK:
No! No!
Wait!
( grunting )
My ship... the Rio Grande...
my brother's on it.
He's got my ticket.
That ship was full, sir.
I checked the list myself.
Quark's name wasn't on it.
His brother Rom
did go aboard,
but he was
with a dabo girl.
A dabo girl?
What?
Looks like he
sold your seat.
No...
No, you don't understand.
You don't understand!
I can't stay here!
I'll be hung.
Call the ships back!
I'll pay anyone
five bars of gold-pressed
latinum for a seat!
Ten bars.
( breathing heavily )
Twenty.
( sighs )
Clear.
No resistance at all.
Minister Jaro's prediction
was correct.
The Federation
has tucked its tail
between its legs.
Where are the Bajoran officers
who worked with Starfleet?
Where is Li Nalas?
Perhaps they knew
this old station
could never
withstand a siege
and they abandoned it
with Starfleet.
The most strategic position
in the entire sector--
at the mouth of the wormhole.
Hmm.
Had I been Federation Commander
I would not have abandoned it
so easily.
KIRA: Can you believe,
a year ago, I was living
in a camp like this?
Only not quite so nice.
DAX: Have I mentioned
how allergic Trills are
to insect bites?
Really?
Well, the biochemical
connections
between host and symbiont
can't tolerate the... Oh!
Whoa! What's that?
Is that a spider or a dog?
KIRA:
Palukoo.
The Bajoran moons
are full of them.
Oh, I suppose you used
to make them your pets
and, uh, sing songs about them
around the campfire.
No. We used
to eat them.
There it is.
Are you sure this thing
is supposed to fly?
Oh, I've been in
a lot worse.
I guess
the Bajoran resistance
must have had
a lot of short pilots.
Ha, no, just
short engineers.
They were always
building these things
without thinking.
Encouraging.
Just bend your knees.
You'll fit.
Now, the real trick will be
to fire up these thrusters
after all this time.
It was hard enough
to get them going
when they were being used
every day.
We'll get them fired up.
You don't have
to worry about that.
Oh, you're sure, huh?
Yep.
I have no intention
of getting stuck here
eating palukoos.
We should inform Minister Jaro
of our success immediately.
KRIM:
You're too eager to receive
his plaudits, Colonel.
What's the status
of the internal security net?
WOMAN:
Completely disabled,
General.
Scan the Operations Center
for organic material.
Organic?
The station's Security Chief
is apparently missing.
The shape-shifter.
It's possible he left
with the evacuation ships
or perhaps there's
something more here
than meets the eye.
Yes, sir.
Scan six times an hour
at random intervals.
MAN:
Minister Jaro on subspace, sir.
Minister, I'm pleased
to inform you
that we've encountered
no resistance so far.
JARO: Good news. Then
the Federation has withdrawn.
We monitored
the evacuation
of three vessels
several hours ago.
When I announce that we've
secured the station
it will certainly impact...
Minister, I urge caution.
The battle for this station
hasn't even begun yet.
Do you expect the enemy
to return, General?
I'm not convinced
they ever left.
The internal security net
has been sabotaged.
We have no way of tracking the
movements of anyone on board
which suggests
someone didn't want
to be that easily found.
Kira?
Perhaps.
She is unaccounted for.
So, too, is Security Chief Odo.
So is Li Nalas.
You're right.
Li Nalas would have never
abandoned Bajor.
He must still be there.
Let me reemphasize that you are
to take every necessary step
to keep Li Nalas alive.
Dead, he's a martyr.
Alive, he seals our victory.
Understood.
Once you have him
Li will see the wisdom
of giving you his support.
I'll offer him
anything he wants
to make sure he does--
short of becoming the
next Kai, of course.
You have a unique ability
to build a consensus, Essa.
Bajor has been waiting
for a leader like you.
Leaders like us.
If I am so favored
by the Vedek Assembly.
You don't have
to worry about that.
26 hours after
I'm sworn into office
I'll direct
the Vedek Assembly
to elect you Kai.
Together, we will
rebuild Bajor.
You got it!
( coughing )
Don't turn the engines off.
We'll never get them
started again.
Let's go.
Thank you, Tobin.
Dax, come on.
( grunts )
Oh, the hell with it.
If it's going to fly,
it's going to fly.
Problem?
No, everything's wonderful.
Ow!
The knees.
Oh, listen to that sound.
That sure brings back
some memories.
How did you ever win a war
in these things?
We were the insects,
Lieutenant.
The Cardassians were
just as allergic as Trills.
Is the proximity system
working?
( thumps )
I think so.
All right, let's see
if we can get out of here
without bouncing off any walls.
You're playing
right into their hands.
If you're so convinced
they're still here
how can you sit
and wait for them to attack?
They have no interest
in attacking.
What makes you
so sure?
Because I understand
military tactics.
They are vastly outnumbered.
If we divide
our forces...
The primary sensor array
was sabotaged, sir.
As soon as we tested it,
the sub-net shorted out.
You can let
your engineers
play with the machines.
I'm sending out search parties.
Eat hearty.
The replicators crash
in 16 minutes.
This will have
to last a while.
Combat rations, Chief?
Couldn't you have
replicated something
a little more palatable?
You don't like
combat rations?
A French onion soup
would have really been nice.
Miracle of science,
these little combat rations.
Timed-release formula
of all the nutrients
the body needs
for three days.
I love 'em.
The only thing I miss
about the Cardassian front.
Sisko to all units.
You can thank Chief of
Operations Miles O'Brien
for your repast this
afternoon.
Oh, you haven't made
any friends here, Chief.
Or should I say chef?
O'BRIEN:
Julian!
Well, I would have expected you
of all people
to appreciate
the nutritional value
of combat rations.
Actually, when I was
in med school,
I designed
an incredible candy bar
which was far superior
in food value.
Am I the only one
that doesn't think
this is funny?
ODO: Odo to Sisko.
Go ahead.
Stand by.
There's a patrol approaching.
I'll get back to you
in a minute.
A five-man unit
is about to begin
a search of the cargo deck.
That puts them closest to me,
Commander.
SISKO:
Stand by, Doctor.
O'BRIEN:
Maybe we should
send someone
with a little
more experience.
Someone who can
run the show, like Li.
SISKO: No, I need him
here with us.
Doctor, move your unit
to Cargo Bay 6.
You know what to do.
And let me reemphasize--
use deadly force
only if absolutely necessary.
Aye, sir.
We're on our way.
Happy hunting.
BASHIR:
I wouldn't get
too close to that.
It's thorium isotope.
Prolonged exposure
could have very
nasty consequences.
Bashir to Sisko.
SISKO: Go ahead.
Mission accomplished.
We have our first five
prisoners of war.
Preparing to establish
a high-altitude
orbit of Bajor.
Navigational sensors
aren't functioning.
No problem.
No problem?
Big problem.
Without navigational sensors...
We'll have to fly
by the seat of our pants.
Great.
Seat-of-the-pants technology.
You Starfleet types are too
dependent on gadgets and
gizmos.
You lose your natural instincts
for survival.
My natural instincts
for survival told me
not to climb aboard
this thing.
I'd say they were
functioning pretty well.
I know the terrain
of Bajor.
We ought to be able to
recognize a landing site...
( explosion )
What the hell was that?
I have no idea.
None of the sensors
are functioning.
Someone's firing at us.
Initiating evasive maneuvers.
I'm reading the EM signature
of an impulse engine.
Let's see
what we're dealing with.
Welcoming committee from Jaro.
We'll never outrun them in
this.
You're right.
We'll have to
even the match.
And how do you intend
to do that?
New playing field.
I'm taking us down
into the atmosphere.
They won't be able to use their
impulse engines down there.
If they want a fight
they'll have to fight
on our terms.
Come on.
Get down.
O'Brien to Sisko.
SISKO: Go ahead.
They've got us
pinned down in here.
On our way, Chief.
Now.
( crying out )
All right, they've
gone to thrusters.
That evens things
up a little.
If you consider
two against one even.
There is one problem.
One?
The guys flying
those ships?
Yeah?
Used to be the guys
flying these ships.
Test the phaser banks.
Full power.
Good.
Uh, not so good.
Phaser locks are dead.
There's no way to aim.
Sure, there is!
I know. I know.
Seat of the pants.
With your eyes, Lieutenant,
not your pants.
Just point at them and fire!
You fly, I'll shoot.
Hang on.
Where the hell's
the other one?
I think we found him.
Thruster power's falling.
They must have hit
a plasma conduit.
Got any fire gear?
Check under the seat.
I think I got something.
Got it.
That's it?
That's it.
Might as well jettison
the plasma tank.
Thrusters are gone.
Plasma tank ejected.
Can you see any openings
where we can put down?
Six kilometers ahead
at 2 O'clock.
Uh, anything a little closer?
How much closer?
How about right here?
MAN:
Sir, up here.
One of the Ferengi's
holosuites is in use.
Don't try it.
Get their weapons.
SISKO: This is
Commander Benjamin Sisko.
Please listen very carefully.
The Cardassians are supplying
the weapons for this coup.
Ridiculous.
No Bajoran would ever
accept help from them.
Jaro doesn't know.
The Cardassians are using
the Kressari
to deliver the weapons
to the Circle.
That is a Federation lie!
The proof is on its way
to Bajor.
Once this evidence is
presented, the coup will end.
We don't want to fight you
or hurt anyone.
Your officers will be our
guests for a while.
I hope they won't mind
Starfleet combat rations.
Day, what the hell
is going on?
I was taken prisoner.
The Federation
is behind all this.
Sisko spoke to me.
So, Commander,
you didn't abandon your post,
after all.
What did he say?
Nothing of consequence.
Why did he let you go?
I promised them amnesty--
a promise I have
no intention of keeping.
General, the security net
is back on line.
Scan for their
communication devices.
Not picking up a thing, sir.
Then they must be
in a shielded location.
The Cardassians used
duranium composite
to shield all the conduits.
Then that's where we'll
find Commander Sisko.
They found the raider,
and they're spreading out.
We can't stay here.
I'll slow you down.
The only thing
that's important now
is to get the evidence to
the provisional government.
It would be
a lot more convincing
if it comes from you.
No, the evidence
speaks for itself.
You have to leave me.
That's an order,
Lieutenant.
The Federation officially
left Bajor yesterday.
You're no longer
my commanding officer.
I can't walk.
Yes, you can.
You are being a fool, Dax.
Don't talk to
your elders that way.
MAN:
You two,
check over there.
MAN:
They couldn't have gotten far.
( indistinct conversation
continues )
( groans )
ODO: Odo to Sisko.
I hope you're not
still on level five.
No, we're on
three. Why?
Because they're about to fill
the conduits
with anesthizine gas,
starting with level five.
Chief?
Well, it's a good idea.
Kind of thing
I might have come up with.
We better get out of here,
and soon.
We should have heard something
from Kira and Dax by now.
Well, if they didn't make it
we're all fighting
for a lost cause here.
We still have
an ace in the hole.
Me?
Mr. O'Brien, get the units
ready to move out.
Aye, sir.
Jaro's plan depends
on the military's support.
Without it, the coup fails.
And you think
I can sway the generals.
Right now, there's
only one general
I'm concerned with--
the one that's here.
He's picked the wrong side
and we've got to convince him
of that.
Would you rather
follow a politician
or Bajor's greatest war hero?
I've done everything
I can to help.
I'd die for my people, but...
Sure, you would.
Dying gets you off the hook.
The question is,
are you willing to live
for your people--
live the role
they want you to play?
That's what they need
from you right now.
( gasping and panting )
Kira?
Kira, you're safe.
You're at the monastery.
I... the last thing
I remember...
The entire city
saw your ship go down.
The searchers who found you
are from my order.
Dax?
She's fine.
She's changing clothes.
We've got to get to
the Chamber of Ministers.
The Cardassians...
I know.
Lieutenant Dax told me.
Oh!
Careful.
Careful. You've just had
a broken hip mended.
How long have I been here?
Six hours.
Six hours?
We have to get out of here.
The Chamber of Minis...
Good, you're up.
Here, put this on.
Why are we...?
It's the only
way we can get
into the Chamber
of Ministers.
Members of religious orders
are the only ones
who can travel safely
in the streets.
I'm going to escort you.
No. No, we have to go
alone, Bareil.
I can't be responsible
for your safety.
Of course you can't
but I can be
responsible for yours.
No...
Please, don't argue.
So, what do you think?
Think?
The nose.
Oh... it's flattering.
I'm thinking of keeping it.
Quark, leave it.
I can't leave it.
It's all that I am.
My personal mementos...
my family album...
It's full of gold-pressed
latinum and you know it.
Who told you?
Your mother did
the day you were born.
Never make fun of
a Ferengi's mother!
Rule of Acquisition,
Number 31.
SISKO: Sisko to Bashir.
We're in position.
We're stationed
above Airlock 14, sir,
awaiting your signal.
You've got it.
Just make as much noise
as you can
before you surrender, Doctor.
We'll make them think
there are 200 of us
instead of 20, sir.
Bashir out.
Twenty-one.
Come on.
Now!
Fine! Fine.
I'm coming.
Proceed with level three.
OFFICER:
General, the enemy
has attacked our position
at Airlock 14.
They have attacked?
We must have
flushed them out.
Seal all airlocks.
Lock all docking clamps.
This is Colonel Day.
All security units
to Airlock 14.
Let me see what's
going on down there.
Surveillance cameras
have been sabotaged.
How many of our men
are stationed
by that airlock?
OFFICER: Four, sir.
OFFICER #2:
Security to General Krim.
The enemy forces at
Airlock 14  have surrendered.
We've taken
several prisoners.
Bring their leaders to me
for questioning.
Aye, sir.
O'BRIEN: Please don't
resist, General.
We don't wish
to use deadly force.
My name is Li Nalas.
Perhaps you've
heard of me.
Guards, stop that woman.
WINN: What is this blasphemy?
I am Major Kira Nerys,
and I come with proof
that the Cardassians
are behind Minister Jaro's
attempt to take control
of the government.
Major Kira has long been
an outspoken opponent
of the provisional government--
of reason,
of progress,
and now, finally, of me.
I'm honored
to be included, Major.
But I have no intention
of allowing you to disrupt
the orderly transition of power
with these wild charges.
This is a manifest pad
from a Kressari vessel.
It bears the thumb scan
of a Cardassian gul
who transferred weapons
to that ship.
Those weapons were taken
by the Kressari to the Circle.
This coup will deliver Bajor
back into the hands
of its greatest enemies.
Are you willing to live
under Cardassian rule again?
I assure you there's nothing
to these accusations.
Then you should have
no objection
to an inspection
of this manifest, Minister.
No, of course not.
We'll adjourn
for the time being.
And let me say
that I completely
support this investigation
and fully intend to cooperate.
( crowd clamoring )
KRIM:
Colonel, you deliberately
withheld information
that was to be
communicated to me.
Information?
Regarding the Cardassians.
Lies, that's all they were.
We have been told
the Chamber is in recess,
while evidence
of Cardassian involvement
is being examined.
The Circle is
broken, Colonel.
I'm returning
to the surface immediately
to consult
with the Ministers.
I expect I will
be asked to resign.
Commander, since the
provisional
government has prevailed
I believe it is appropriate
to return the command
of this station to Starfleet.
Well-fought, sir.
No.
Commander!
( groaning )
( tricorder beeping )
( panting )
( chuckles )
Off the hook... after all.
( sighs deeply )
( tricorder beeping )
( steady tone sounds )
Somehow, you figured,
now that he was here
things would be better.
You know, he'd...
he'd find a way
to make things better
because he was a man
who could do that.
A great man.
I wish I knew
where we could find
others like him.
Major, there are heroes
all over Bajor.
I'm sitting with one.
I'm sorry.
I... don't feel
like celebrating tonight.
Excuse me.
Sir, can I ask you something?
Sure.
About Li Nalas.
Mm-hmm.
Well, listening to Kira
talk about all he was,
all he did,
all he was going to do,
she makes him sound like
he was larger than life
like he was some kind
of military genius.
But the Li Nalas
I fought with...
Chief, Li Nalas was the hero
of the Bajoran resistance.
He performed extraordinary
acts of courage for his people
and died for their freedom.
That's how the history books
on Bajor will be written,
and that's how
I'll remember him
when anybody asks.
Yes, sir.
DAX: Dax to Sisko.
The Ganges has just docked
at Pad C, Benjamin.
Acknowledged.
Excuse me, sir.
Dad.