SISKO: Station Log, Stardate 47182.1.
DS9 has been temporarily evacuated
due to a violent plasma disruption.
Until the disturbance ends,
we'll be forced to maintain the station
with a skeleton crew.
-How are we holding up?
-So far, so good.
I'll say one thing for the Cardassians,
they built this place to last.
Just in case it doesn't...
I've got the Orinoco
prepped and ready at Pad C.
Any word from Chief O'Brien?
He and Odo checked in about an hour ago.
They sealed off the airlocks
in the upper and lower pylons
and were moving on to the docking ring.
-Sisko to O'Brien.
-O'Brien here.
-What's your status, Chief?
-Almost done, Commander.
We've sealed all the airlocks
on levels 21, 22, and 23.
We still have to check the outer bulkheads
to make sure there hasn't been
any crystallization
from the plasma discharges.
It shouldn't take too long.
O'Brien out.
( faint banging )
Did you hear that?
Hear what?
I could have sworn I heard something.
-Quark!
-What are you doing here?
ODO: You're under strict orders from Sisko
to stay in the bar.
I'm not a prisoner, Odo.
I volunteered to stay
and help you protect the station.
The only reason you volunteered
is because there wasn't enough room
on the evacuation shuttles
for 600 bars of gold-pressed latinum
which still doesn't explain
what you're doing out here
in the docking ring.
I was saying good-bye to my brother.
Your brother?
His shuttle left three hours ago.
Funny... it's only been three hours
and I'm already lost without him.
Oh, please!
Don't try to tell me
you've been sitting out here
all this time pining for Rom.
I know, I know.
He couldn't find a cup of water
if you dropped him in a lake,
but even if he is an idiot,
he's still my brother.
And you'd betray him in a second
if it suited your interests.
That doesn't mean I don't love him.
( Odo scoffs )
-Chief, do you have any brothers?
-As a matter of fact, I have two.
And did you ever have
to say good-bye to them?
-Sure, when I joined Starfleet.
-And did it bring a tear to your eye?
I suppose so.
Well, try explaining that to him.
The storm's intensity is up 37%.
Is there any way of telling
how long it'll last?
Your guess is as good as mine.
Plasma storms are extremely rare.
But look on the bright side.
This gives us a great
opportunity to study one.
Oh, lucky us.
You should see the view
from the Promenade.
It's simply amazing.
-I assume the Promenade is secure.
-Oh, yes, sir. I've struck the sails
and battened the hatches, so to speak.
DAX: Benjamin,
you better take a look at this.
( console beeping insistently )
I'm detecting a small vessel
headed this way at one quarter impulse.
-KIRA: They're hailing us.
-On screen.
I can't get a visual.
MAN: ( static )
This is the Cargo Ship Ekina.
We've been caught by the storm.
Our engines have been severely damaged.
We need emergency assistance.
Can you read me?
Repeat, this is the Cargo Ship Ekina...
I've lost it.
Can we get a transporter lock on the crew?
No, there's too much interference.
Engage the tractor beam.
Bring them in to the closest docking bay.
There might be casualties.
I'll get down to the Infirmary.
SISKO: Good idea.
-Sisko to O'Brien.
-O'Brien here.
Chief, we've got some storm victims
coming in to Docking Bay Five
who may be in need of assistance.
I'll have to release the emergency seal
on the airlock before
they can board the station.
On my way.
Stand clear.
( coughing )
Are you all right? Is anyone hurt?
KLINGON: Not yet.
-What the hell do you think you're doing?
-No questions.
This is a nice way to show your gratitude.
We just saved your lives out there.
You see? The ever-helpful Federation.
-So predictable.
-Listen, friend
in case you haven't heard
the Federation and the Klingon
Empire are allies now.
( spits )
The Empire is governed
by doddering fools
and frightened old women
who aren't worthy of the name "Klingon."
Mareel! The combadge.
-This one must be the shape-shifter.
-Go on! What are you waiting for?
You're a Trill.
You! Shifter! Inside.
And what if I refuse?
Please, do as he says
and no one will get hurt.
KLINGON: Now! Or this one dies.
Let's go...
Ally.
Chief, were there any casualties?
-That depends on you.
-BASHIR: What's this all about?
( grunts )
Yeto, get the Ferengi.
-Any more questions?
-Don't hurt him.
Mareel! The box.
Put it in your stasis chamber.
Now, or I will destroy it.
Is that supposed
to be some kind of threat?
They've got Odo in there.
I see... Well, in that case...
I'm still not getting a response
from O'Brien or Odo.
Run a level-3 security scan.
KLINGON: Don't bother.
Please, take your hands
away from the controls.
Now!
Get to the center of the room.
Do as he says.
Don't worry, Verad.
It's going to be all right.
Get with the others. Move!
Your turn, little man.
Don't forget to disable the backups
as well as the primary systems.
It's my fault, Commander.
They caught us by surprise.
Somehow, they must have neutralized
the security systems
-in the docking ring.
-How did they manage that?
I'm not sure but I've got
a pretty good idea.
We ran across Quark
in an airlock a little while ago.
When this is over Quark
and I are going to have a little talk.
Do you know him?
Ah, Yeto.
It's such a pleasure
doing business with Klingons.
You're so, um... punctual.
I see your ship was rescued
according to plan.
Um, I've got your merchandise right here
-but I don't see any latinum.
-You Ferengi!
You think you're so clever,
but you're stupid.
Now, now, there's no need
for name-calling.
If you don't want
these liquid data chains,
I'm sure I can line up
dozens of other buyers.
Go right ahead.
Yeto,
you expect me to believe
that you've come all this way,
braved the storm, just to tell me
that the deal is off?
Stupid Ferengi!
( chuckling nervously )
-I said no one moves.
-I'm Commander of this station.
-What is your business here?
-You'll have to ask my employer.
I'm... I'm sorry about all this.
If everyone would just cooperate
-I promise it will all be over soon.
-What will be over soon?
QUARK: This is an outrage!
I demand to be released at once!
-Enough of your whining!
-Who are these people?
What do they want from us?
Funny. I was about
to ask you that question.
-That's enough.
-SISKO: I agree.
Now tell me what you want here.
Dax.
I... want Dax.
-She's not going anywhere with you.
-No, no. I don't want the girl.
I only want what is rightfully mine...
What should have been mine years ago.
I want Dax.
DAX: The symbiont, Benjamin.
He's come to steal my symbiont.
You can't remove Jadzia's symbiont.
If you do, she'll die.
He knows that, Doctor.
I'm...
I'm sorry about all this.
Please, believe me,
-I wish I didn't have to do this.
-Then don't.
I don't have a choice.
I... spent my whole life
trying to qualify for the joining.
I... studied constantly,
every day, every waking hour.
I sacrificed... everything,
and then I went before
the symbiosis evaluation board
And...
They reduced my entire life to one word...
Unsuitable.
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
Neither of my parents
or my sister underwent symbiosis,
and they live happy
and productive lives.
Only one Trill in ten
is chosen to be joined.
That's easy for you to say.
They chose you.
I was one of the lucky ones.
Now it's Verad's time to be lucky.
KIRA: Why Dax?
There are thousands
of symbionts on Trill. Why her?
I did research. I worked it all out.
The Dax symbiont is the best match for me.
We have mutual interests,
science, diplomacy--
Verad, there is another reason,
isn't there?
SISKO: The wormhole.
After you've stolen the symbiont
you plan on escaping
to the Gamma Quadrant, don't you?
Can you think of a better place
to start a new life?
I understand your frustration
but there could be dozens of reasons
why the board
didn't select you for symbiosis.
They have to be very careful.
An improper joining
can cause permanent psychological damage
to both the symbiont and the host.
They were only looking
after your best interests.
Your best interests maybe, but not mine.
All they've done is condemn me
to a life of... of...
Mediocrity.
Well, I refuse to accept that.
I--I'm not going to spend
the rest of my life dreaming
about what I could have been.
What I should have been.
I deserve... more...
-and I'm going to get it.
-Yeto, T'Kar, it's time.
I'll have no part in this.
I... I understand.
( groans )
( gasping )
VERAD: Keep away from him, Doctor.
There, you see? I've taken the first step.
Even if I don't get what I want,
my life is over,
so either you help me
or you and your friends will die.
It's your choice.
He'll help.
I don't want anyone else hurt
because of me.
But you have to give me your word
that no one else on this station
will be harmed.
I... I promise.
Doctor.
Do as he says, Julian, please.
Let me treat
Chief O'Brien's phaser wound first.
BASHIR: It won't take long.
There's an emergency
medical kit in the console.
Get it!
Hold still, Chief.
( groaning )
There.
There should be no permanent damage.
Apply this every 20 minutes or so.
It should help the wound regenerate.
Enough stalling!
Do as he says, Doctor.
This is no time to be a hero.
Take them to the Infirmary.
This isn't over, Dax. I promise you.
SISKO: Dax...
DAX: I know, Benjamin.
You'll do everything you can.
And just in case it isn't enough,
I want you to know it's been fun.
MAREEL: Let's go.
Good luck.
It won't be long now, and then you'll see.
Everything will be just as I promised.
I know.
-What's that?
-BASHIR: It's a delta wave inducer
to keep you asleep during the operation.
It also increases
your body's natural endorphin production
-to help accelerate the healing process.
-I don't want it.
I strongly recommend that you use it.
The surgery
will be much easier on you if--
I don't want your advice.
I want to be awake.
Use a neuroelectrical suppresser
and set up a monitor
so that I can watch the procedure.
That way, if you run into any trouble
I can assist you.
Now, let's get started.
I'm sorry, Jadzia.
Don't blame yourself, Julian.
You did everything you could.
I...
This will help you sleep.
Thank you.
Forgive me.
How long can Dax survive
without the symbiont?
Once the symbiont is removed
the host usually dies within hours
but Jadzia is young and healthy.
Bashir will do what he can.
-She'll make it through the night.
-That still doesn't give us much time.
No talking!
-( groaning )
-No!
( hissing )
( loud grunting )
( groaning )
I don't want to kill you,
Commander, but I will!
This is ridiculous.
Don't you realize
they're going to kill us?
What are you people sitting around for?
Do something.
Do you have any suggestions?
Why should I have any suggestions?
I'm not the military mastermind.
-I'm just a victim of circumstances.
-Victim? Really?
Then maybe you'd like to tell me
how four armed terrorists
got by our docking ring security grid.
Security grid?
I don't know anything about...
Save it, Quark.
You crossed the line this time.
You sold us out
and now Dax may die because of it.
Well, whatever happens next,
one thing is certain you are through here.
( snarls )
-Are you all right?
-I'll live.
Don't try that again.
I don't want to have to hurt anyone.
Tell that to Jadzia.
That's different.
Do you really believe that?
You heard Verad.
They didn't leave him any other choice.
-No, that's his reason. What's yours?
-I owe him.
I grew up on the streets of Khefka IV.
I never would have made it out of there
without Verad.
What was he doing on Khefka IV?
He was the communications clerk
at the Federation Consulate.
He used to visit
the accommodation house where I worked.
I used to help him relax.
When he was recalled to Trill,
he asked me to go with him.
-We've been together ever since.
-And that's it?
He got you out of a bad situation
and now you're willing to kill for him?
I owe him my life.
If there's anything
I can do for him I'll do it.
Even if it means losing him?
Losing him?
After the surgery Verad
won't be just Verad anymore.
He'll be a blending of Verad, Dax,
and all the previous hosts,
their memories, their knowledge,
even their personalities.
Verad told me
that you'd say things like that.
I know he'll change.
He'll be smarter, more confident,
but in all the important ways,
he'll be the same.
I'm sorry,
but if he told you that, he's lying.
Once a Trill
is joined it's like a rebirth.
He'll be an entirely different person.
If you think
I'm going to betray Verad, you're wrong.
It doesn't matter
what you say. I love him,
and I'm going to stand
by him no matter what.
VERAD: I never doubted it.
Verad.
No, not just Verad.
I'm Verad Dax.
Take this.
Come on, we haven't got much time.
Just move it back and forth over the wound
-in slow, even strokes.
-Why bother?
She'll be dead in a few hours anyway.
Not if I have anything to do with it.
Now, help me.
Why should I?
She let herself be slaughtered
like a mindless t'gla.
If she wanted to live,
she should have fought back.
She did what she did
to save the rest of us.
Then she is a fool,
and she deserves her fate.
Now listen to me, Yeto,
or whatever your name is.
I don't give a damn
about your warrior ethic
or your Klingon philosophy.
This woman is dying,
and I need your help to save her.
Now, take this instrument.
Well... so the little human
has some spark after all.
( beeping erratically )
Come on. Come on.
( beeping steadies )
Julian.
Oh, thank God. I thought I'd lost you.
The symbiont.
It's gone.
Oh, everything went perfectly.
The operation was a complete success.
I feel so alone.
I've got you stabilized.
If only we could get the symbiont
back in time.
I'm scared, Julian.
You're not going to die. Do you hear me?
I'm not going to let you die.
( shallow breathing )
I've never felt so empty.
BASHIR: Just rest.
Dax?
That's right, Benjamin.
It's me.
Curzon, Tobin, Jadzia, all the others,
they're all a part of you now.
It's amazing.
So many ideas. So many memories.
Eight lifetimes of memories.
It must be incredible.
It's better than I ever imagined.
The station must look very different
to you now.
It does. I... I know this place.
( chuckling ) And I know you, Benjamin.
Of course you do.
Remember when we first met?
-Pelios Station.
-Anastasia?
And that trip we took
to the Cliffs of Bole?
( both men laughing )
SISKO: All the months we served
aboard the Livingston.
And Science Officer Kustanovich.
What was it?
Eight helpings of Andorian Redbat?
( laughing )
SISKO: I don't think I've ever seen
someone eat so much.
-Remember my wedding?
-I remember your bachelor party,
or some of it anyway.
And the time we discovered the wormhole.
My, my, my.
One of Jadzia's proudest moments.
And now that woman is bleeding to death
in the Infirmary.
-I'd rather not discuss that, Benjamin.
-You have to discuss it, Dax.
You know as well as I do
we can't let her die.
She's not going to die.
She'll live on in me.
Jadzia's memories will live on,
but Jadzia herself will die,
and you'll have killed her.
You think I don't know that?
I'll never be able to forget it,
but I promise you, Benjamin
I'll do all I can to make up for it.
I'm not going
to the Gamma Quadrant to hide.
There are entire worlds who can benefit
from my knowledge and experience.
-I can help them, and I will.
-I have a better idea.
-VERAD: What's that?
-Help Jadzia.
Come with me down to the Infirmary.
Put the symbiont back where it belongs.
I can't do that, Benjamin,
even if I wanted to.
Don't you see? It's too late.
The integration is already underway.
But there's still time to stop it.
Jadzia's life can still be saved.
Don't listen to him.
He's just trying to confuse you.
It's all right, Mareel.
Benjamin, the symbiont is still weak
from the operation.
If we attempt another joining so soon,
it might not survive.
-VERAD: Are you willing to risk that?
-I am.
The question is, are you?
Why are you wasting your time with him?
Because he's my friend!
Now, go watch the others.
We are still friends, aren't we, Benjamin?
I hope so.
Come with me down to the Infirmary
and prove it.
I can't do that.
Then you're not the Dax that I know.
Our friendship is over.
-Here, drink this.
-What is it?
Senarian egg broth.
It'll keep your strength up.
All right, don't drink it.
It makes no difference to me.
Hold on.
Thank you.
He even looks different, doesn't he?
The way he stands,
the way he moves, talks.
-He's better than he was.
-I'm glad you think so.
I do.
Really? The way he dismissed you before?
-Verad never did that.
-He's under a lot of stress.
SISKO: Verad was under stress
the minute he stepped onto this station,
-but he never turned on you, did he?
-What's your point, Commander?
I think you know.
You're trying to turn me against Verad.
Verad no longer exists.
You know that better than I do.
All right, then.
Verad Dax, but it won't work.
-Nothing has changed between us.
-You really believe that?
Yes.
All right.
Then make me believe it.
Go in there and talk to him.
Talk to him about what?
I don't know. Whatever you want.
I'm sure the two of you
have a lot to say to one another.
-I don't want to disturb him.
-Why not?
Because I don't want to!
Well, look at him,
sitting in there all alone.
-He needs you.
-That's enough.
I don't understand
why you're being so reluctant.
This is the perfect time
for the two of you to get reacquainted.
-I said that's enough!
-VERAD: Mareel.
Is anything wrong?
No, everything's fine.
Good.
Be careful.
I wouldn't want anything to happen to you.
( grunting and groaning )
I got him! I got him!
( roaring )
Stay back.
( groaning )
Maybe we should talk about this, huh?
( grunts )
My ear.
( moaning )
Pathetic.
Mareel, take him to the Infirmary.
( moaning )
-( screaming )
-What is it now?
Please... it hurts.
All right. Hold on.
The damage
appears to be fairly superficial.
( whispering ) No.
But Ferengi ears are incredibly sensitive.
So I'd better run some further tests.
( moaning loudly )
The storm's intensity's dropped
another 20%.
I know this has been
hard for you, Benjamin.
It's been hard for both of us
but it's almost over.
MAREEL: Good.
I'm getting tired of waiting here.
-How are you feeling?
-Better than ever, thanks to you.
I couldn't have done this without you.
I would have spent the rest
of my life a mediocre man
only dreaming about what might have been.
You know what you have to do.
You just worry about getting
through the wormhole.
The Klingons and I will make sure
that no one stops you.
Remember, I don't want you staying here
any longer than you have to.
Give me an hour,
then head for the wormhole.
The runabout's on Pad C.
The sooner you leave,
the sooner I can follow
and the sooner we'll be together.
It's going to be all right, isn't it?
Just wait for me at the rendezvous point.
( loud moaning )
Stop whining
or I'll put you out of your misery.
It's not his fault.
He's got a deep contusion
of the auricular lobe
and a possible dislocated malleus.
In a Ferengi, either condition
could be fatal.
But if you want him to stop,
give me a hand with this.
I'm not your nurse!
Look, let's not go through that again.
Just hold this against his ear.
( high-pitched whining )
( screams )
Not too hard.
( groaning )
Just another second.
Relax.
( gasps )
There.
Thank you, Doctor. I feel better already.
How is she?
I have her stabilized
but there's no telling
how much time she has left.
We've got to get the symbiont
back before it's too late.
-What are you doing?
-Odo's in here.
He is?
Yes, and we've got to get him out.
-Are you sure?
-Quark!
If only we knew the access code.
Allow me.
( beeping softly )
Ah... standard
Delgorian locking mechanism.
Sophisticated...
but vulnerable if you know its weaknesses.
Hand me that laser scalpel.
Uh-huh.
Mm-hmm.
( clicking )
( beeping )
( lock releases )
It's a gift.
The storm's decreased another 15%.
Excellent. That should be more than enough
to allow safe passage to the wormhole.
Verad to Yeto.
Yeto, report!
The doctor must have overpowered him.
-The doctor? Impossible.
-It's the shape-shifter.
He must have freed the shape-shifter.
T'Kar, get me to the ship.
You'd better take a hostage just in case.
I'll go with you.
VERAD: I'd love your company, Benjamin,
but somehow, I don't think you
have my best interests at heart.
-Kira, I hate to inconvenience you--
-That's all right.
If Odo's free there's no way
you're getting off this station.
Mareel?
Good luck.
Well, Benjamin, I guess this is good-bye.
Not many friendships
last over two lifetimes.
I wish we could have made it three.
You'll be seeing me again, Verad.
So...
Where's this rendezvous going to be?
-You don't really expect me to tell you.
-No, but I hope you like it there,
because you'll be waiting
for Verad a long time.
-How would you know?
-You told me yourself.
I saw the look on your face
when he asked you to wait for him.
The plan was, he was supposed
to get there first.
That he would wait for me,
not the other way around.
Well, maybe it was an honest mistake.
A slip of the tongue.
No. He lied to me.
He's never lied to me before.
He's not coming.
He doesn't need me anymore.
No, you're wrong.
He does need you now, more than ever.
You never give up, do you?
-I told you, I'm not going to betray him.
-I'm not asking you to.
I'm asking you to save him,
to help us save him.
All you care about is Jadzia.
That's right, and you care about Verad,
and we can save them both.
Don't you see?
Dax and Verad
were never meant to be joined.
We've got to remove the symbiont
while there's still time.
If you hurt him...
I'll kill you.
I don't doubt it.
The ship... it's gone.
That's because I released
the docking clamps.
Looks like that good-bye
was a little premature.
Don't be ridiculous.
You're not going to shoot me.
What makes you so sure?
This is Dax you're talking to, Benjamin.
We both know that if you shoot me,
even on stun,
you risk killing the symbiont.
If I let you go, Jadzia dies.
But Dax will live.
What's one girl's life
compared to eight lifetimes
of knowledge and experience?
You're not going to shoot me.
You know that, and so do I.
Good-bye, Benjamin.
Verad.
Don't call me Benjamin.
( groans )
I feel strange.
So empty.
It's over now, Verad.
The symbiont is back where it belongs.
So close.
I had it.
I had it, and...
Now I'm alone.
You're not alone, Verad.
I'm here.
I'll always be here.
I can't remember any of it.
The knowledge...
The confidence...
It's all gone.
BASHIR: Commander?
Jadzia.
Are you?
I'm fine.
I remember it all, Benjamin,
everything he thought, everything he did,
and it's so sad.
I guess...
He'll always be with me.