BASHIR:
Medical Log, Stardate 47229.1.
Chief O'Brien and I
have been working overtime
to prepare for the arrival
of a new cartographer.
Ensign Melora Pazlar
is the first Elaysian
to join Starfleet,
and, as such, requires
special accommodations.
I haven't seen one
of these in 300 years.
I'm surprised
it was even on file
in the replicator's
data bank.
It isn't.
Ensign Pazlar sent me
the specifications.
She really uses one like this?
Her normal anti-grav unit
isn't going to work here.
Same problem we had with
the Starfleet cargo lifts.
Cardassian construction
just isn't compatible.
KIRA:
Ops to Bashir.
The Yellowstone has just
docked at Airlock 14, Doctor.
We're on our way.
BASHIR:
Just think of what she's gone
through to get here, Jadzia.
What it must be like
to adjust to our gravity
after growing up on a planet
with such low surface gravity.
Doctor, we've done
the best we can
with the ramps.
The Cardassians obviously
didn't have her in mind
when they built
this place.
Well, I've managed to modify
the maximum vertical clearance
of the chair three centimeters,
to a slope of 56 degrees.
Well, that still leaves
a lot of places
around here
she won't have access to.
Can't we just use
the transporter
to help her get around?
It makes sense to me,
but she sent word that it
wasn't acceptable to her.
I wonder why.
BASHIR:
I know exactly why.
She went through Academy
the same way.
Once her basic needs are met
she refuses
any special assistance.
She's extraordinary.
You make it sound as though
you've known her for years.
I almost feel as though I have.
I've pulled all
her personnel
and medical files
to get ready.
Her quarters-- they're ready,
aren't they?
I've got the bumps on the head
to prove it.
Thanks, Chief.
Let me know if there's
anything else I can do.
That'll be something to see--
when we switch off the gravity
and she flies around the room.
( panting )
Ensign Melora Pazlar
reporting for duty.
Welcome to DS9, Ensign.
I'm Chief Science Officer
Jadzia Dax
and this is...
Dr. Bashir, we spoke
on subspace.
Good to meet you in person.
I see you have
my trolley car
ready to go.
As requested.
Can I help?
I'm fine, thank you.
That's better.
You've modified it.
Yes, I wanted
to give you
as much mobility
as I could.
I've been practicing
on the model
I requested for a month.
Well, it's no problem.
We can replicate
the other design.
No, I'll just have to adapt.
DAX:
I will be accompanying you
on your survey mission.
I really don't think that'll be
necessary, Lieutenant.
I'm perfectly capable
of piloting a runabout.
Commander Sisko
thought that it...
I'm sure he thought
what every officer
I've ever served with
has thought--
that I need extra help
to get the job done.
Please tell him I don't.
Commander Sisko
wouldn't allow any Ensign
to take a runabout
into the Gamma Quadrant
the day after
she arrives.
I'm sure
the Chief Science Officer
has more
important things to do
than chart a sector
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Um, here we are.
You didn't modify
the specifications
I gave you
for my quarters, did you?
Not one iota.
You can control the gravity unit
with this device.
If you'd care to try it out...
Thank you, I will.
It was a pleasure
meeting both of you.
MAN:
Paltriss only created
80 of them, each a...
a work of art.
And I've come into
the possession of 42.
Forty-two?
My world will
honor your name
for returning
the rings of Paltriss
to his birthplace.
Honor my name
all you like
as long as your honor
is accompanied
by 199 bars of
gold-pressed latinum.
I heard you drive
a hard bargain.
Shall we celebrate
our closing the deal
with another drink?
( sighs )
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
We're not open yet
but if you'll
come back in...
Have another
drink on me.
Fallit Kot, is
it really you?
How long has it been?
Eight years.
Eight long years.
Oh, it can't be.
I must say,
you look terrific.
Tanned, toned up...
all that baby fat
has disappeared
from your face.
You don't keep extra weight on
where I've been.
( laughs uncomfortably )
Just passing through
are you?
I bet you
have business
in the Gamma Quadrant.
You always had a sharp eye
for fresh territory.
Oh, I'm not going
to the Gamma Quadrant.
My business is
right here with you.
With me?
That's right.
I've come to kill you, Quark.
DAX:
I've gone through
her mission profile
and she certainly seems
to know what she's doing.
Nevertheless, this is
her first deep
space assignment.
And it doesn't make
sense to me to...
( electronic whirring )
Here she is.
Welcome, Ensign.
I'm Commander Benjamin Sisko.
Am I late?
No, not at all.
It looked as though the meeting
had already begun.
Dax and Bashir
were just telling me
about your request
to pilot a runabout alone.
Wouldn't it have
been more appropriate
to include me
in that conversation?
I was getting a briefing
by my senior
officers, Ensign.
We discuss personnel
matters all the time.
I'm sorry if I seem
overly sensitive,
but I'm used
to being shut out
of the "Melora problem."
The truth is, there is
no "Melora problem"
until people create one.
( panting )
This may sound
ungrateful
because Dr. Bashir has
been wonderfully helpful
in the preparations
for my arrival,
but frankly, I wonder
why a medical opinion
is necessary
in this discussion.
Julian knows more
of your capabilities
than any of us.
I don't need a medical opinion
to tell me my own capabilities.
Ensign...
I simply object
to being treated
like someone who is ill.
I don't see anybody doing that.
Try sitting in the
chair, Commander.
No one can understand
until they sit in the chair.
I've been in one chair
or another
since I left my home world.
My family gave me this cane.
It's made from the wood
of a garlanic tree.
They had no idea
what it would be like
to live off-world
in what you consider
"normal" gravity.
Only a handful of Elaysians
have ever left home,
but I always knew
that I had to be one of them.
I dreamt about exploring
the stars as a child,
and I wasn't going to allow
any... handicap--
not a chair,
not a Cardassian station--
to stop me
from chasing that dream.
You must feel
a great deal of pride
about everything
you've achieved.
And I've achieved that,
Commander,
without being dependent
on anybody.
To be honest,
I prefer to work alone.
It's simply easier for me.
( sighs )
I am not comfortable
sending you alone
into the Gamma Quadrant.
Sir... I can focus
on the job better.
I-I can work at my own pace
without being a bother
to anyone else.
Lieutenant Dax will
be going with you.
Yes, sir.
When do you wish to leave,
Lieutenant?
Your schedule
is fine with me.
Then tomorrow at 0730.
( electronic humming )
( door chimes )
( humming stops )
Is it working?
The low-grav
field actuator.
I just heard it go off.
It's working fine.
So you were just...
Oh, um... for me
it's like slipping
into a hot tub
at the end
of a long day.
Really?
I'm a shower man, myself.
Look at this.
Is this your husband?
Boyfriend?
Doctor, if you came
for an apology...
I apologize.
Apology?
My speech wasn't intended
to attack you personally.
I'm sure you never set out
to attack anyone personally,
but you do seem to attack a lot.
That's rather insensitive
of you, Doctor.
Julian.
I'm no longer your doctor.
I see.
You've decided I need a friend.
Ooh, was that an attack?
You see, you do it
so well, with such charm
it's hard to tell.
I really don't mean to...
Sure you do.
I beg your pardon?
Of course you mean to.
All of these broad shots
you fire--
they're just your way
of keeping the rest of the
universe on the defensive.
Has to be.
You're too good at it.
Well, uh...
it always seemed to work
pretty well.
Until now.
Well, that is the nicest thing
you've said to me.
Or anybody else.
Are you hungry?
I came here
thinking about
asking you to dinner.
Then afterwards,
we'll go dancing
I suppose.
Ooh, Red Alert.
I'm sorry.
Well, come on.
There's a new Klingon
restaurant open on the Promenade
if... you like
that sort of thing.
All right.
( laughter and conversation )
Dinner is served.
I didn't
order dinner.
What better way to mollify--
( chuckles )
satisfy a hungry traveler
than with a delicious
home-cooked meal?
Starting with a delicate
Vak clover soup.
( dish shatters )
Why spoil your appetite
with soup?
Here's the real treat.
Jumbo Vulcan mollusks
sautéed in rhombolian butter--
a taste so exquisite,
it's to die for.
Uh...
or to live for, for that matter.
Do you know dabo,
Fallit?
It's a wonderfully
entertaining game
and easy to learn.
( snaps fingers )
I took the liberty of lining up
a couple
of excellent tutors I know.
Be sure to ask them
about their "double down"
betting strategy.
( chuckles )
If I haven't
made it clear
I intend your stay here
to be as pleasurable
as you could ever imagine.
So...
allow me
to propose a toast.
To...
old friends.
Old debts.
Gagh Tek Or?
Shall I order
for us both?
All right.
Um, let's see now.
We'll have some racht,
of course.
racht...
And a double order
of gladst, no sauce, please.
gladst... usu bal.
And a side order
of zilm'kach.
Is that too much for two?
zilm'kach.
Drak doo.
May I?
Don't be alarmed.
Excuse me, Julian,
I can't eat this.
I know how
it looks, but...
P'kar tel Durg Le Frakn'l?
Dug a bul, rah'tar!
D'tel klop a bul!
Pak't pol!
D'kar tel G'denna!
( chuckles )
I like a customer
who knows
what she wants.
( laughing )
G'denna.
There's nothing worse
than half-dead racht.
Gagh Tek Or!
When I was ten,
my father was
a Federation diplomat
on Invernia II.
One day, when we were
out on a remote
part of the planet,
we were hit by a
massive ionic storm,
and while we were
waiting it out
we found an Invernian girl,
about my age, who was sick.
After the storm cleared,
my father went for help,
but it was too late.
I sat there and watched her die.
The next day when he returned,
his guide told us that we
could have treated her
with a simple herb
that was growing
all around.
I could have saved her life.
And so you started
to study medicine.
Actually, first
I started to study tennis.
Tennis?
I really thought I could
make a career out of it.
You must be very good.
Well, I used to think so
but then I went to my
first major competition.
My opponent served first
and I heard the ball
bounce past me.
The computer announced
it was good
and I realized
I was in trouble.
Turned out, I had more talent
at medicine than tennis.
( chuckles )
( clears throat )
Well, I, um, have
an early mission tomorrow.
I better get some rest.
Of course.
( door chimes )
Dax to Pazlar.
Computer,
level-1 security access.
Ensign Pazlar?
Computer, locate
Ensign Melora Pazlar.
COMPUTER:
Docking Level 22, Section 14.
Section 14?
( panting )
We need to get you
to the Infirmary.
It's my own fault.
I decided...
I could use an extra
astrometric array
after going through
the mission profile again.
I came to the storage
bay to get one.
My mind was already
in the Gamma Quadrant.
I wasn't... paying
enough attention
to what I was doing.
I guess my boot
didn't make the lip
of the door.
I fell on my controls.
Dax to Bashir.
Ensign Pazlar's had
a, uh, minor accident.
We need to see you
in the Infirmary.
BASHIR:
Acknowledged.
I'll be there in three minutes.
What kind
of an architect
would deliberately
design a raised rim
at the entrance
to every door?
So much for the dangers
of the Gamma Quadrant.
I didn't even
make it there.
You will.
There's no concussion.
You can reschedule your
mission for tomorrow.
It was so...
( sighs )
Flopping back and forth
like a broken toy.
I didn't want anyone
to find me like that
but I couldn't
get up by myself.
Why didn't you
wait for Dax
before you went
into an area
that was unmodified with ramps?
I didn't need Dax
if I'd just paid attention.
Melora...
no one on
this station
is completely
independent.
In space, we all depend
on one another to some degree.
I just want you all to know
that you can depend on me.
You've proven that.
Now what do the rest of us
have to do to convince you?
Of what?
That you can depend on us.
Have you ever heard
of the work
Nathaniel Teros did
with low-gravity
species 30 years ago?
Neuromuscular adaptation.
It had no practical
success at all.
No, but the principles
were sound
and a lot of progress
has been made
in neurochemistry
since then.
You think someday
I could throw away
the chair?
Theoretically...
perhaps.
Would you like
to come in?
Oh, no, I know how much
you look forward
to turning down
the gravity.
Don't let that stop you.
You may want
to brace yourself
until you get
used to it.
Come on, Julian.
What do I do?
Just give
a gentle push.
It's easy.
( hesitant gasps )
Oh... oh... oh...
Oh, oh... Oh!
This is astonishing!
I can't tell you how curious
I was about this.
Oh.
Most people are.
Sometimes they make me feel
like a carnival attraction.
So usually I prefer
to keep everyone out.
Well, thank you...
for letting me in.
( clears throat )
He's my brother.
Who?
Oh.
Setting course 28 mark 142.
Confirmed.
Computer... any
Vulcan études on file?
COMPUTER:
Affirmative.
If you have
no objections.
Computer, play us
something by Delvok.
Delvok never seems Vulcan to me.
There's too much... emotion
in his music.
( quiet plucked-string melody
playing )
It's pretty.
Tell me something,
Lieutenant--
you think there's room
for... romance
in Starfleet?
I think so.
You've made it work?
Mmm, now and then.
I mean really work.
Oh... really work.
Yes.
Well, for that, I'd
have to go back, um...
150 years.
Oh...
that's a long time.
Could it be that Dr. Bashir's
bedside manner has won you over?
Our species are just
so... different.
Since when has that
ever stopped anyone?
I knew
a hydrogen-breathing Lothra
who fell hopelessly in love
with an Oxygene.
You're kidding.
How could they even be
in the same room?
40 minutes a day without
their breathing apparatus.
That's all.
57 years they
were together.
What-What about...
career conflicts?
Two friends of mine
from the Academy got engaged
even though they knew
they were being assigned
to different starships.
Subspace relationships?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, that's a tough one.
They may not be together
for a year or more,
and even then
for only a few weeks.
Love across light-years--
it's just so...
It lacks intimacy.
You could say that.
I finish my mission here,
I move on to the next one.
What kind of future is that
for a romance?
Look at the alternative.
I guess.
Oh, it's you.
Don't be so happy
to see me.
All right, I won't.
Odo, there's
a desperate criminal
on board the station.
You wouldn't be talking
about Fallit Kot,
who just finished eight years
at a labor camp
for hijacking a shipment
of Romulan ale,
and whose name appears
right next to yours
on the original
indictment?
I had nothing to do
with the hijacking itself.
I was only the,
uh... middleman.
Trafficking
in stolen goods
should have been enough
to get you your own cell
at that Romulan camp.
Unless, of course,
you sold out your partner.
I can honestly say
justice was served.
I would imagine Fallit Kot
is looking for his own
kind of justice now.
He threatened to kill me.
What?
Nothing.
Just a passing thought.
Odo, he means it.
Nothing I do
seems to change his mind.
You've got to do
something.
I'll do my job, Quark.
Yeah.
Unfortunately.
( sighs )
( door opens )
Racht, anyone?
I've been waiting
for you.
I've got something
to show you.
What is it?
It's a computer model of
an elevated neural output
from the brain's
gross motor cortex.
It's stimulating
acetylcholine absorption
to increase tensile strength.
The neuromuscular
adaptation theory?
It was theory
30 years ago,
but with the development
of neo-analeptic transmitters
it's not even that complicated.
It's just
that no one's ever gone back
to reexamine the ideas
of Nathaniel Teros.
Until now.
This...
could actually work?
No more servo controls.
No more chair.
Have I done
something wrong?
Not that I'm aware of.
We have something
in common.
We do?
I don't like
Quark either...
but I can't
let you kill him.
Kill him?
Did he tell you
I was going to do that?
I know of your
history together.
Let bygones be bygones,
I always say.
And I always say you can
tell a man's intentions
by the way he walks.
How do I walk?
Like someone carrying a lot
of weight on his shoulders.
Must be the memory
of those Romulan bricks
I carried for eight years.
Must be.
But you can't lock a man up
for the way he walks,
can you?
Well?
I'd say he's a man
with nothing to lose.
As opposed to me.
I have no reason
to hold him for now
and he knows it.
I'll watch him
the best I can,
but I suggest you carry
a combadge with you
at all times.
Call me at the first
sign of trouble.
What if the first sign
is the last sign?
You people sell
pieces of yourself
after you die,
don't you?
Yes.
I'll buy one.
My heart is pounding.
I'd like to think that
has more to do with me
than the neo-analeptic
infusion.
Would that also explain
why my backside
is getting warm?
Well, that's more likely
the result
the neuromuscular
tissue stimulation
due to the increased activity
in the motor cortex.
I'd say that's enough
first time out.
It's good that you've already
been using your muscles
in this gravity environment.
It'll make it
easier to adapt.
Feel any different?
No.
Nothing at all?
I'm sorry, Julian.
The acetylcholine absorption
is precisely
at 14% above normal.
Increased
tensile strength
would be the
inevitable result.
Julian?
I can lift my leg.
Your neural pathways
are beginning to adapt.
Endurance
and coordination
might take a while,
but we should
have you walking
within the hour.
How's the upgrade coming?
O'BRIEN:
We've been
able to get it
to about 70%
of what we'd get
with a standard EPS,
but it looks like
that's going to be...
( turbolift whirring )
Well, I'll be damned.
I wanted to give you
our first day's mission summary
myself, Commander.
A pleasure, Ensign.
Julian, how did you, uh...?
Oh, it was simply a matter
of increasing the output
on the brain's
motor cortex.
Someone else's research,
actually.
I just dotted the I's
and crossed the T's.
Well, you'll get your name
in the medical journals
for this one.
Yeah, I know, I...
Julian...
I don't know
how to tell you this
but I'm not sure
I can make it...
Easy does it now.
It's just the first day's
treatment beginning to wear off.
Thank you.
Nothing to be concerned about.
Look, I better get you
back to your quarters.
I want you to get a good
night's rest tonight.
Oh, thank you.
Habitat Ring, Level 14.
With each
progressive treatment
you should get stronger,
and the effects
should last longer.
( panting )
What about this?
A low-grav
environment now
would really confuse
your motor cortex.
I understand.
Julian...
You let me fly
for the first time.
I let you walk.
We're even.
I'll see you in the morning.
Lights.
Computer, turn on...
( glass clinks on table )
Quark to Odo...
No one can
hear you, Quark.
It's just you and me.
Fallit.
Oh, I wasn't prepared
to entertain this evening,
but make yourself at home.
Oh, I already have.
What's mine is yours.
All you have
to do is ask.
I'm tired of
your gifts, Quark.
All I want is your
miserable life.
Wait!
Everything's negotiable.
( choking )
Believe me...
I'm worth much more
to you alive.
How's that?
( croaking ):
How does 199 bars
of gold-pressed latinum
sound to you?
( gags )
It's a start.
The mattress felt like rocks,
and every one of my muscles
ached all night long.
You'll adjust to that
after a few more
treatments.
This time the
effects should last
for several hours.
( exhales )
Exactly when does this
become irreversible?
Melora... if you're
not certain...
No, I'm sure it's just
some strange form
of buyer's remorse.
I'll be fine.
Tell me exactly
what you're feeling.
Last night,
I just missed...
I didn't feel like me.
If you want to end
your dependence
on the chair
and the servo controls,
you're going
to have to give up
the low-grav environment.
You knew that that
was the trade-off.
And it seemed
like a good trade.
Until I realized I
couldn't do it anymore.
If I could just spend...
I'm just concerned that
going back and forth
could ultimately lead
to a loss of fine
motor control.
Meaning?
Your ability to perform
complex tasks
could be affected.
The effects are
fully reversible
for the next few days.
We can pull the plug
at any time before then.
But after that,
if all goes well,
your motor cortex impulses
will kick in on their own.
Permanently.
It's starting to wear off again.
I don't understand myself.
How could I possibly
have second thoughts?
This would mean
real independence.
It's everything
I ever wished for.
But then I start
to think about home
and how I won't ever
be able to go back.
Well, maybe just
for a short visit
but... never really go back.
The Little Mermaid.
Mermaid?
It's an Earth fable
by Hans Christian
Andersen.
She trades
her magical life under the sea
for a pair of legs
to walk on land.
Didn't she live
happily ever after?
( sighs )
Ashrok.
Right on time.
May I present my longtime
business partner, Fallit Kot.
For your
inspection.
Exquisite.
Then our transaction
is complete.
Not quite.
I'll be taking
them, too.
They warned me
about you!
Not true!
A deal is a deal-- Rule
of Acquisition Number 16.
Kot...
you got what
you came for.
Now let's be
reasonable.
( yells )
Pick it up.
Pick it up!
Move!
Hurry up!
Move! Move!
Let's go.
( alarm sounding )
Priority-1 Security
to Level 22, Section 5.
I'm sure Julian
would understand.
Besides, he can still
publish the results
from your
first treatments.
Both of you--
back in the ship.
Let's go!
Move it!
KOT:
Come on, move it!
Now, get us
out of here.
He's already shot a man.
Do as he says.
I'll just wait
in the back.
In the front,
where I can see you.
There-- hurry up.
I'm moving
as fast as I can!
She's an Elaysian.
She needs motor support
in our gravity.
They're in the Orinoco.
Docking clamps
have been released
thrusters engaged.
Ready a tractor beam,
open a channel.
Open.
This is Commander
Benjamin Sisko.
Return to the station at once.
No reply.
Engage the tractor beam.
They've locked onto us
with the tractor beam.
Open the channel
to that Commander of yours.
Release this ship
or I'll kill a hostage.
SISKO:
I'm willing to negotiate
your freedom,
but first release those...
Didn't you hear
what I just said?
( whimpering )
No, I have
something special
in mind for you.
Do I make myself clear?
Release the ship now.
SISKO:
Doctor, Chief-- with me.
Beam us to the Rio Grande.
Give us ten seconds
and then disengage
the tractor beam.
Understood.
Energizing.
They've released us.
Through the wormhole.
What was that?
I'm not sure.
What was it?
Another ship coming
through the wormhole.
Take us to warp.
We haven't even
set a course yet.
I don't care about the course,
just go to warp.
If we don't
set a course,
we could warp ourselves
into oblivion.
Fine, set a course.
Just get us out of here.
They're powering up
their warp drive.
Stay with them.
Engaging warp engines.
Can we beam them
aboard at warp?
I wouldn't recommend that.
KOT:
Get the phasers ready.
I'm not going
to fire at them.
Oh, you'll do it
or you'll die.
It's your choice.
Fine.
Then I hope
you can fly this ship.
Just sit down
and do what
I told you. Now.
Quark, how well
do you know this man?
We've been friends for years,
not counting today.
DAX:
Well I suggest you
explain to him
that Starfleet
isn't going to give up
and stop chasing us.
That's true, Fallit.
You don't know
these Starfleet types.
Then we'll all die.
Great, we escape
and he's got
something "special"
planned for me.
We don't escape
and I just die
with everyone else.
I'm I missing
a choice here, Fallit?
KOT:
Be quiet, Quark.
They've dropped out of warp.
Go to impulse.
Sir, their gravity
generators are off.
Melora's alive.
Gravity's
been reinstated.
All engines are down.
Come on, Doctor.
I think we have
the situation
in hand, Commander.
Sisko to Rio Grande.
Everything's
under control.
We're going home.
O'BRIEN:
Aye, Commander.
Setting course
for the wormhole.
Why didn't
the phaser kill me?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe all the
neurostimulants
we've been pumping
into your body.
That's what I was
wondering, too.
You know, it might make
an interesting side
effect to the treatment.
It's worth exploring...
Julian... I'm not going ahead
with the treatments.
Well, you can always
try it again someday
if you change your mind.
I don't think I will.
I like being
independent.
But to give up
everything I am
to walk... on land...
well, I might be
more independent,
but I wouldn't
be Elaysian anymore.
I'm not sure what I'd be.
Besides, maybe independence
isn't all it's cracked up to be.
I kind of like how it feels
to be dependent on someone
for a change.
And I'm glad you
got me to unlock
the doors
to my quarters
so I could finally let someone
into my life.
So am I.
KLINGON CHEF:
♪ Aler acht'jar ♪
♪ T'lembda boool-gah toh-gal ♪
♪ T'lembda boool-gah
to lohh... ♪
Oh, you must
be exhausted.
Uh, if you don't
want to stay...
No, let's just sit
a while and listen.
♪ Rom ara Rom Rom-rom ♪
♪ T'el Do'a, Do'a... ♪
I want to remember
all of this.
♪ Rom ara Rom Rom-rom... ♪