( snoring )
ODO:
All right, Morn.
You know the rules.
No sleeping on the Promenade.
Go home.
QUARK:
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
The risk is to you,
Lieutenant.
I could probably think better
without your hand on my thigh.
Now, how did
that get there?
( snickering )
So, uh, what's it
going to be?
Confront, evade,
acquire, retreat...
Confront.
( groaning )
Yes!
Doesn't she
ever lose?
QUARK:
Tell me, Lieutenant
how'd you get to be
so good at tongo?
Actually, it was Curzon
who played it all the time.
Well, that explains it.
It's Curzon who's beating
us-- not this female.
This female happens
to be a better player
than Curzon ever was.
And a prettier one, too.
Maybe so, but I still
prefer a Ferengi female--
one who never
wears clothes,
never talks back,
and never
plays tongo!
Is that really how
you prefer your women--
naked and submissive?
You find such
a lifestyle appealing?
Ah, don't you wish?
I do,
I really do.
All right.
The opening risk is at
five strips of latinum.
The purchase is at three
the sell is at eight.
( whispering )
Absolutely not.
This isn't the proper time!
I'm trying to concentrate.
I'm sorry, Brother.
It's this insolent
young waiter's fault.
My apologies, Quark,
but I really think
you should try this.
What is it?
A way to double
your beverage profits.
Taste it.
You see, just as I told you.
He immediately
reached for his drink.
So I did.
Amazing.
You don't even
realize you're thirsty.
What are they?
Gramilian sand peas.
They inhibit the secretion
of the salivary glands
while drying out
the tissues of the tongue.
It works every time.
If you replace
your complimentary
dishes of lokar beans
with Gramilian sand peas,
you won't be able
to fill your customers'
glasses fast enough.
What's your
name again?
Pel.
So, what do you think
about my idea?
I think
I agree with
the 59th Rule
of Acquisition.
Free advice
is seldom cheap.
True, but
the 22nd Rule says
a wise man can hear
profit in the wind.
I see you know
your Rules.
All 285 of them
and the various commentaries
on them, as well.
I don't plan on being
a waiter forever.
Good, then you're fired.
Shut up, Rom.
When it comes
to business,
my brother has the weak
little lobes of a female.
So, uh, what made you take
a job here at the station?
I wanted to learn
from the very best.
Uh-huh, which
brings to mind
the 33rd Rule
of Acquisition.
BOTH:
It never hurts
to suck up to the boss.
( laughing )
( beeping )
DAX:
What's that?
The Grand Nagus Zek's
personal subspace
frequency.
ROM:
I wonder what he wants.
Why do you look so surprised?
I told you I'd be back.
Uh, I've looked forward
to your return, Nagus.
Still the perfect
little toady, eh, Quark?
I try to be.
Then listen carefully.
The Ferengi expansion
into the Gamma Quadrant
is about to begin.
I'd like you to be
my chief negotiator.
Me?
That's right.
I'm offering you an opportunity
to make more profit
than you ever dreamed of.
All you have to do is earn it.
( sighing )
Can I interest you
in some Hupyrian beetle snuff?
I don't think so.
Major?
No, thank you.
Well, suit yourself.
More for me.
( snorting )
( sneezes )
Little late, aren't we?
( blows nose )
So you wanted
to see me, Commander?
I understand you're
planning to host
a business conference
here at the station.
Yes, with the Dosi,
a race from the Gamma Quadrant.
A very profitable
opportunity for all concerned
I might add.
Profitable for
the Ferengi, maybe.
Are you implying
something, Major?
Me? Not at all, no.
The Ferengi reputation
speaks for itself.
A reputation for honesty
and decency and reliability.
You always know what to expect
when you do business
with the Ferengi.
KIRA:
Which is why
if you're smart
you don't do business
with the Ferengi.
I think you've made
your point, Major.
As misinformed and misguided
as it may be.
Besides, how we do business
is no concern of yours.
Except when you conduct
your business on this station.
In other words, Zek,
Grand Nagus or no Grand Nagus,
if we allow you to hold
your negotiations here
and we find out
you're cheating the Dosi,
I'll see to it you never
set foot on this station again.
Did anyone ever tell
you your eyes shine
with the brilliance of
Kibberian fire diamonds?
Not that I recall.
Well, they do.
So, tell me, Major,
could Bajor use
50,000 kilos of
brizeen nitrate?
Of course, we could.
With that much brizeen,
we could fertilize
the entire
northern peninsula.
Well, I've recently
come into possession
of 50,000 kilos
of brizeen nitrate,
and to show you how much
your cooperation means to me,
I'll let you have
the entire shipment.
I'll still need your assurances
that the Dosi will
be fairly treated
while they're here.
You have my word.
Good.
Then it's settled.
Now, let's see--
50,000 kilos at, uh,
25% of our usual price.
25%? You just said
you were giving
it to them.
Well, you're
right, Commander.
We're all friends here.
So I'll let you
have it at cost.
I have
a better idea.
Why not consider
the nitrate
as a gift to the
people of Bajor?
A gift?
That doesn't sound
very profitable.
It depends.
On what?
On whether you want
to conduct business
here or not.
( laughing )
Your negotiating skills
aren't bad
for a hu-man.
Your nitrate will be
delivered promptly.
Anything else you need,
come see me personally.
Well, Quark, I've been involved
in some very profitable
opportunities in my time,
but my lobes are telling me
that this may be
the most profitable opportunity
in Ferengi history.
Imagine that.
And part of those profits
will be mine.
Profit, fame, power--
as much as you want.
Tell me, uh, Nagus, what exactly
is this great opportunity?
I can sum it up
in one word--
tulaberries.
Tulaberries?
Exactly.
Go on.
Well, they're
the main ingredient
in tulaberry wine.
Your job will
be to purchase
10,000 vats
from the Dosi.
We're going
into the wine business?
Within
a single year,
we'll have made
tulaberry wine
the most popular drink
in their entire sector.
That's enough!
Oh, I like it--
very distinguished.
Tell me, Nagus--
how are tulaberries going to be
the most profitable opportunity
in Ferengi history?
Do I have to spell it out
for you?
If you don't mind.
Tulaberries
will establish
a Ferengi presence
inside the Gamma Quadrant.
And once we get our foot
in the door,
they'll never
get it out.
Yes, I see!
Tulaberries, Quark, tulaberries.
Tulaberries.
I wonder what
they taste like.
Who cares what
they taste like?
They're an opportunity
to get a Ferengi foot
in the Gamma
Quadrant door.
And it'll be
your foot, Brother.
I'm so proud.
I'm going to make
history, Rom,
and I'm going
to be rich.
And I have
the Grand Nagus
to thank for it.
He must really
like me.
Just remember one thing--
the bigger the smile,
the sharper the knife.
48th Rule
of Acquisition.
He has some nerve.
I warned you
about that fellow.
Pel, do you mind telling me
what you meant just now?
Did you ever think
about why the Nagus
has put you in charge
of such a lucrative opportunity?
Isn't it obvious?
He knows I have the
lobes for business.
That's only part of it.
I refuse to stand here
and allow my brother
to be insulted.
You're fired.
Shut up!
Go on.
If the negotiations
are profitable
then the Nagus becomes
the greatest hero ever,
but if they fail,
he's going to need
someone to take the blame.
You mean me?
All I'm saying is, be careful.
I never heard
such ridiculous lies.
He's just jealous
of your success, Brother.
No, he's right.
If something
goes wrong,
it'll be my fault.
Then you're going
to need help, Brother.
Yes!
Someone to serve
as your consultant
during negotiations.
Yes!
Someone like me.
No.
Uh, I've been thinking
about what you just said,
and, uh, I probably
could use some help
during these
negotiations.
I accept.
Good.
Then we're partners.
Not quite-- I don't
need a partner.
I need an assistant.
All right, but I get 25%
of everything you make.
Fifteen.
Twenty.
Done.
But, Brother,
what can I do to help?
You want
to help?
Table six
is waiting.
How do I look?
Nervous.
Who, me?
What have I got
to be nervous about?
Yeah, it's Zek
who should be nervous--
with Quark here
as his chief negotiator.
( gasps )
If you ever
do that again...
Do what?
If you ever
do that again,
I'll stick those 50,000 kilos
of brizeen right up your...
Here they
come!
( shouting )
MALE:
Don't worry
just a minor disagreement.
So, uh, can I get anyone
something to eat?
All right.
Um, in that case,
let's go over our offer.
As you know, the Ferengi
are interested in purchasing
10,000 vats
of tulaberry wine.
In exchange,
the Dosi will receive
what I consider to be
a very fair trade package.
There are some very interesting
items on that list--
a subspace field modulator,
uh, some optical
data processors...
We'll give
you 5,000 vats.
I'm afraid
that won't be enough.
Um, we're looking to establish
a vast distribution network
in the Gamma Quadrant.
We'll need
at least 10,000 vats.
I'm offering you
5,000 vats.
I suggest
you take it.
The Nagus will
never agree.
FEMALE:
This is
a waste of time.
We should be talking
directly to Zek.
I know we should
be talking to Zek.
Then why do you bother talking
to this insignificance?
Now, see what
you've done?
What?
You've made me
look foolish.
I didn't mean to.
Then bring us Zek.
PEL:
The Nagus has asked
Quark to represent him
during these negotiations.
Are you implying
that Zek is too important
to negotiate with us?!
We never meant to imply
anything of the sort.
Because,
if we kill you,
Zek will have
to talk to us.
You want to do business
with the Ferengi,
you talk to Quark.
QUARK:
So how about it?
Do we say 10,000 vats?
We'll think
about it.
Can I help you?
What is it?
DAX:
It's beautiful.
KIRA:
It's latinum.
Excuse me,
I really can't accept this.
Did Zek really think
this was going
to get him anywhere?
Probably not.
But it doesn't stop
a Ferengi from trying.
You sound like you
admire them for it.
I suppose,
in a way, I do.
I don't understand your
attitude about the Ferengi.
That's because you don't
socialize with them
the way I do.
Looking back
over seven lifetimes,
I can't think of a single
race I've enjoyed more.
Did anyone
ever tell you
you have very
strange taste?
I admit, they place
too much emphasis on profit,
and their behavior towards
women is somewhat primitive...
They're greedy,
misogynistic,
untrustworthy
little trolls,
and I wouldn't
turn my back
on one of them
for a second.
Neither would I.
But once you
accept that,
you'll find they
can be a lot of fun.
Evade.
Retreat.
Acquire.
Confront.
Did I say "acquire"?
I meant "evade."
You said "acquire."
Well, I meant "evade"!
Why don't we just
play the round over?
That sounds fair.
Who asked you?
And shouldn't you
be plotting strategy
for tomorrow's negotiations?
Believe me, Nagus,
I've thought of nothing
else all evening.
That must be why
you're losing so badly.
And I think, by tomorrow,
we should have an agreement.
Well, I've been thinking, too,
and 10,000 vats
of tulaberry wine aren't enough.
Tell them we want 100,000.
100,000?
But I'm not sure they'll even
agree to sell us 10,000.
100,000 vats would mean
more profit for them and for us.
Now, do as I say!
Or I'm going to take over
the negotiations myself.
I think raising the stakes
is a brilliant idea.
You do?
It'll show the
Gamma Quadrant
we mean business.
No wonder Quark says
you're a genius.
Oh, he says that, does he?
All the time.
That's very touching.
Now bring me
some fresh tube grubs.
These are losing
their crunch.
Right away.
So, I believe the next
challenge goes to you.
I think I'll pass
on this round.
Such loyalty
must be expensive.
You can't buy
that kind of loyalty.
You can where
I come from.
Is the Nagus always
this impatient?
He wants results, and he
expects me to get them.
But he's not making
my job any easier.
100,000 vats-- that's
a lot of tulaberries.
You'll get them.
How can you
be so sure?
Because you're good,
and with me helping you,
you're even better.
Why are you being
so nice to me?
For 20% of your profits.
Why else?
Fair enough.
NAGUS:
Quark, where are my grubs?
Coming.
Mmm. Now this is
what I call fresh.
DAX:
I didn't know the Replimat
had a Ferengi menu.
It doesn't.
I like to try
new things.
That's unusual
for a Ferengi.
I never heard of a Trill
who could play tongo.
I guess that makes
us both unusual.
You know, I was impressed
by your show of loyalty
to Quark last night.
He deserves it.
That's not the point.
Any other Ferengi
would've let Zek
pick him to pieces.
But you're not like
any other Ferengi
I've ever met.
Quark really
likes you.
He talks about you
all the time.
You know he
once convinced me
to go up to a holosuite
with him?
Turns out, he recreated
the bedroom I slept in
as a child.
He overheard me
describing it to Kira.
Of course, most of the details
were wrong,
but it was
a very sweet gesture--
up until he tried
to kiss me.
That sounds
like Quark.
( both laughing )
I don't care
what anybody says.
I love him.
So do I.
You really do,
don't you?
What?
Love Quark.
Don't bother
trying to deny it.
I've seen the way
you look at him.
Please, keep
your voice down.
Does he know?
He doesn't even know
I'm a female.
You're a woman?
Please lower your voice.
Please.
I knew there was something
different about you.
But I've never met
a Ferengi woman before.
You probably
never will again.
On my world, women aren't
allowed to leave the house
or wear clothes,
or learn to read.
And you wanted more.
Why not?
I'm as smart as any man.
So I made myself a pair
of synthetic lobes
and became one.
Why come here?
To acquire profit,
of course.
There's only one thing
I wasn't counting on.
Falling in love
with Quark.
What do you think
I should do?
I don't know.
But I do know there's
more to life than profit.
Pel, it's time!
We don't want to keep
the Dosi waiting.
Hurry!
Okay, now, I
think our best...
( murmuring approval )
Excuse me.
Ah, Major.
Did that shipment
of brizeen nitrate
arrive on time?
Yes, it did.
Good.
And here you are
to thank me.
( smarmily ):
Have a seat.
Actually, I just stopped
by to return this.
Why, is something
wrong with it?
No, it's lovely,
I just can't accept it.
Then I suppose
a night of wild,
passionate romance
is out of the question?
That's right.
Just thought I'd ask.
( gasps )
Dax must be crazy.
Nice view, isn't it?
Don't tell me
the negotiations
are already over.
That's fast work, Quark.
Now, let's see the contract.
There is no contract.
No contract?
But you offered to buy
100,000 vats, didn't you?
Yes.
And?
And that's
when they left.
The room?
The station.
What?
I begged them to stay.
This is a catastrophe,
a complete catastrophe.
This was your big chance, Quark,
and you blew it!
You may have
seriously harmed
future Ferengi
opportunities
in the Gamma
Quadrant!
Hold on a minute.
We said we're going
to get you the tulaberries,
and that's exactly
what we're going to do.
We are?
How?
We're going
to travel
to the Gamma Quadrant,
find the Dosi,
and get them
to sign the contract.
And how do you plan
to get there?
We'll take your ship.
My ship?
Oh, and I suppose
you expect Maihar'du
to pilot it for you.
We don't need Maihar'du.
I can pilot
the ship myself.
It's up to you, Nagus.
Do you want
those tulaberries or not?
All right.
You can use my ship,
but I'm warning you, Quark--
either you get the Dosi
to sign that contract,
or you'll be tending
that worthless little bar
for the rest of your life!
I've waited
my whole life
for an opportunity
like this.
So have I.
So far, it hasn't
turned out
quite the way I planned.
It's not over yet.
I still don't understand
why the Nagus
is suddenly insisting
on 100,000 vats.
Nor do I.
You don't think
he's purposely trying
to sabotage
the negotiation?
Why would he?
I have no idea.
Hmm. One thing's
for certain--
he knows more
than he's letting on.
About what?
Everything--
the tulaberries,
the Dosi,
even the Gamma Quadrant.
Well, if you
ever figure out
what he's up to,
make sure you tell me.
Don't worry, I will.
So far, the only thing
I've done right
is pick you
as my consultant.
I'm glad
you feel that way.
Now, if we can only
make some profit.
Quark, there's something
you should know.
Oh, you're too late.
I already know what
you're going to say.
You do?
It's no secret.
It's not?
I admit you've been
a great help to me,
but you agreed to a 20%
share of the profits,
and that's all
you're going to get.
I see.
Never place friendship
above profit.
21st Rule of Acquisition.
I'm glad you agree.
Hmm.
Go, just go!
Go!
Oh...
Feeling a little
overwhelmed, are we?
I'm glad
someone notices.
When's Quark due back?
Oh, how should I know?
He never tells me
anything.
He doesn't even bother
to insult me anymore.
Go, go.
It's Pel, that, that
flabby-eared interloper.
He's stealing
my brother's affections.
Hmm, you're better off.
But he's my brother!
Would you let someone
steal your brother?
I don't have a brother.
Not that I
know of, anyway.
But if you did.
Well, I suppose
if I did have a brother,
even one as worthless
as Quark,
I wouldn't let anyone
come between us.
( grumbles )
( panting agitatedly )
There must be something here
I could use against him.
Hmm.
( buzz of conversation )
I've got
controlling interest
so I want to supervise
all operations.
That's ridiculous.
Well, then find
another partner.
Let's not be hasty.
I said, no!
Are you enjoying yourselves,
little Ferengi?
How could we not?
Tell us, Zyree--
what is this place?
This-- this is where
opportunities are made.
Really? I thought it
was some kind of party.
Then you thought wrong.
This is all about profit.
And like the Ferengi,
the Dosi are very serious
when it comes to profit.
( phaser shot, male groaning)
You, take him away.
Very serious.
Look who finally
showed up.
It's about time.
Where are you going?
To get serious about profit.
Hey, watch it!
Oh... it's you,
Ferengi.
Aren't you on the wrong
side of the wormhole?
It certainly
feels that way.
Fortunately, all I need
is your thumbscan
on this very
lucrative contract,
and I can go home.
You had your chance.
Go away!
Not until we finish
our discussion.
( growls )
You... are starting
to annoy me.
Sorry.
I should have killed you
back on that station.
But you didn't because
deep down inside,
you recognize a
good opportunity
when you see one.
Just put
your thumbscan here.
All right, you can
have the 10,000 vats.
100,000.
I told you before
that's impossible!
100,000, and I'm not
leaving till I get it.
Fine.
Then stay.
( groans )
Wouldn't we be
more comfortable
sleeping on the ship?
No, I want to be right here
in case Inglatu
changes his mind.
Don't worry, I don't snore.
Wait!
What is it?
The mattress.
What about it?
It looks lumpy.
Actually, it's very comfortable.
I can't sleep
on a lumpy mattress.
Well, you're in luck, there's
not a lump to be found.
Try it for yourself.
What side do you want?
What are you doing?
Getting undressed.
What does it look like?
You're not going to sleep,
are you?
Why not? I'm tired.
Shouldn't we be discussing
rules of strategy?
There's nothing to discuss.
But you know
what the 103rd Rule
of Acquisition says.
Not offhand.
Sleep can interfere...
And I don't care, either!
Wait!
What is it now?
First a toast.
To what?
To, uh, profit, of course.
( groaning ):
Of course.
Is it warm in here?
It must be the wine.
I hope so.
I was really impressed
with the way
you handled Inglatu.
I was good,
wasn't I?
Now let's get to bed.
Wait!
The look on his face
when you knocked
over that barrel.
That was risky.
The riskier the road,
the greater the profit.
62nd Rule.
That's right.
You really know
your Rules.
And you have
a very nice smile.
I do?
Oh, Quark, I
have something
I have to tell you.
( Quark protesting )
I'm not interrupting
anything, am I?
No, definitely not!
Are you sure?
Positive!
I'll come back tomorrow.
Wait!
No, wait!
This is all a silly
misunderstanding.
ZYREE:
But you seem
to be... busy.
QUARK:
Busy?
Don't be ridiculous.
We can't wait to hear
what you have to say.
Besides, we could use
the company.
Uh, isn't that right?
Absolutely.
All right, then.
Let me give you
some advice--
Inglatu will never
sell you 100,000 vats
of tulaberry wine, not
because he doesn't want to,
but because he can't.
If he can't,
who can? You?
I wish I could,
but there aren't
that many vats
on the entire planet.
Then we're finished.
Not necessarily.
If you really want
100,000 vats
of tulaberry wine,
I can put you in touch
with the right people.
For a price, of course.
Of course.
I always said you were
my favorite Dosi.
Now, um, who do we
have to see?
The Karemma.
Who's the Karemma?
An important power
in the Dominion.
The Dominion,
what's that?
Let's just say, if you
want to do business
in the Gamma Quadrant,
you have to do business
with the Dominion.
"The most profitable
opportunity
in Ferengi history"--
that's what
Zek called it,
but he didn't mean
tulaberries, no.
He meant the Dominion.
That's why he sabotaged
negotiations.
He never wanted to do
business with the Dosi.
He just wanted
to use them
to get to a more
important member
of the Dominion!
Quark, we need to talk.
We are talking.
Don't you want to know
why I kissed you?
You never kissed me.
Yes, I did.
No, you didn't,
and I don't want to
discuss it anymore.
Let's just concentrate
on the Dominion.
I only wish Zyree
would have told us more.
Maybe it's some
planetary alliance
or trading consortium.
Whatever it is,
it's important,
and I want
a piece of it.
Quark, I'm very disappointed.
I really wanted
those tulaberries.
You and I both
know my trip
had nothing to do
with tulaberries.
It didn't?
I must speak
with you, Brother.
Can't you see
I'm busy?
Does the word "Dominion"
mean anything to you?
What have you found out?
You first.
Please, Brother,
it's urgent.
Not now!
I'm waiting.
Well, most of
my information consists
of little more
than hints and whispers,
but it's enough
to convince me
that whoever learns
the secret of the Dominion,
whatever that may be,
will learn the secret
of the Gamma Quadrant.
Unfortunately, the Dosi
don't seem to know very much.
I was hoping they'd lead
us to someone who does.
What would such information
be worth to you?
A lot.
What if I
told you I could
arrange a meeting
between you and a powerful
member of the Dominion?
If you can do that,
I'll see to it
that you earn a percentage
of every Ferengi opportunity
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Ah...
that's a lot of latinum.
Give me... a name.
The Karemma.
I always knew you had
the lobes for business.
( guffaws )
Now may I speak
with you, Brother?
All right, but
make it quick.
( whimpering )
Easy, now.
That's quite a bump
you've got there.
Where's Rom?
Right here, Brother.
Luckily, there
doesn't seem to be
any serious damage.
Uh, if you don't mind,
I'd like to rest here
for a few minutes.
Of course.
I'll be in the other
room if you need me.
Thank you, Doctor.
You haven't told
anybody, have you?
You mean about Pel?
Quiet.
I haven't
breathed a word.
I thought it'd be best
if you told Zek yourself.
Nobody's going to tell Zek
anything, is that clear?
But she's a female...
Not so loud.
Who wears clothes and is
trying to earn profit.
Why, she even quotes
from the sacred Rules
of Acquisition.
Such a female must be
severely punished.
I know that.
Then we'll stop her.
No.
You're scaring me,
Brother.
Could it be you have
feelings for this woman?
Of course not.
Don't you see?
If Zek learns that I've
been deceived by a female,
I'd be ruined.
He'd never
trust me again.
But if you don't tell
him and he finds out,
you're certain
to be ruined.
You have to tell
him, or I will.
Let me go.
I have to save you
from yourself.
Forget about me.
What about the bar?
The bar?
You still want it,
don't you?
Don't you?
Who needs the bar
when I can have
the Gamma Quadrant?
I'll transfer
ownership immediately,
but only on
one condition--
that you never
mention the truth
about Pel to anyone.
Pel?
W-W-What about him?
( both chuckling )
Yeah.
( door chimes )
Come.
Where are your lobes?
Over there.
Well, put them on
before somebody sees you.
No one's going to see me.
Put them on.
Now.
And wrap yourself up.
Have you finished packing?
Am I going
somewhere?
As far away from this station
as possible.
But you need
me, Quark.
I'm the only one
you can trust.
Not anymore.
Well, what did you expect?
I mean, look at you.
You're wearing clothes.
Is that a crime?
As a matter
of fact, it is.
Look, it's just too risky
for you to stay here.
And you can take
this with you.
What is it?
Ten bars of latinum.
To help you
start a new life.
If you're going to
pretend you're a man,
act like one.
Take the profit.
This is not about
profit anymore.
It's about love!
Oh, spoken like
a true female.
I love you, Quark,
and I know you care
about me, too.
Admit it!
What difference
does it make if I do?
You'd never be happy
being a Ferengi wife.
Then come with me
to the Gamma Quadrant.
No one there cares if
I wear clothes or not.
I'd care.
Then I guess
I'd better start packing.
I guess so.
Mmm... mmm... mmm.
( crunching )
Mmm... mmm...
Mmm!
Mmm.
These flaked blood fleas
are surprisingly succulent.
Mm-hmm, you really should
try them, Brother-- mmm...
I'm not feeling
particularly hungry.
Let me guess.
Too busy thinking
about how to spend
all that latinum
we're going to earn?
Well, I don't blame you.
( door chimes )
Come.
I thought you said
she left the station!
I thought she did.
I hope you don't mind, Quark,
but I couldn't leave without
saying good-bye to the Nagus.
I'm glad you stopped by.
I know how much
you helped Quark
during the negotiations.
I predict a big
future for you, Pel.
You certainly have
the lobes for it.
So, you like my lobes?
Pel...
Yes, I do.
Good, then you
can have them!
No!
( screams )
It's a female!
Does this mean
I don't get the bar?
Rom... out.
Quark, this is outrageous!
Now what's going on here?
I-I-I...
Leave him out of this!
You dare give me orders?
You knew about this all along,
didn't you?
I...
So tell me more
about my big future.
You have no future.
I'll see to it that you spend
the rest of your life in prison.
No.
Let me
remind you
that taking business advice
from a female
is a violation of Ferengi law.
I didn't know she was a female.
Stupidity is no excuse.
Now, one more word out of you,
and you are going
to share her cell.
Then, you better make sure
it's big enough for three.
Are you threatening me?
I wonder
what your associates will say
when I tell them you allowed
a female to represent you
in a business negotiation.
I didn't know
she was a female.
Stupidity is no excuse.
I see your point.
It seems that Pel's identity
will have to remain
our little secret,
but it's going to cost you.
My Gamma Quadrant profits.
I've always said you were
a bright fellow, Quark.
Shame on you!
I hope you're satisfied.
I'm sorry...
but it's time
you learned
that when it comes
to accumulating profit,
women are as
capable as men.
Well, do me a favor and
don't tell anybody else.
I should go.
I've booked passage on
an Andorian transport.
You could come with me.
I can't.
I know.
Well, then, I guess
if I can't have you,
I'll take those ten bars
of latinum after all.
( groans )
( sighs )
( door opens, closes )
So, Lieutenant...
you ready for another
night of tongo?
Haven't you lost enough
for one day?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm talking about Pel.
She came by to see me
before she left.
I'm going to miss her.
So are you.
You really think I'd let
anyone come between us?
Nice try, Quark,
but I know you
better than that.
( sighs )