Science Officer's Log,
Stardate 47603.3.
Commander Sisko has assigned me
to investigate an unusual
particle field
detected on the other side
of the wormhole.
Odo has come along
to the Gamma Quadrant
hoping to find clues
to his origin.
So you see, Ensign Manwaring
has spent the last two weeks
avoiding the Assay Office
because he thought
that Freyla was in love
with Lieutenant Strek
but all the while, Strek was
seeing Security Officer Seelee.
And Freyla was waiting for
Manwaring to ask her out.
Officer Seelee has seemed
distracted at work lately.
I'm going to have to talk
to her about this
when we get back to the station.
Odo, I didn't tell you
that story
to get Seelee in trouble.
Frankly, Lieutenant
I fail to see any point
in your story at all
except perhaps to illustrate
the foolish humanoid
preoccupation
with romantic coupling.
The point is that, sometimes,
we don't see true love
even when it's staring us
right in the face.
How fascinating.
Let me give you another example.
You know Lysia Arlin?
The Bolian woman
who runs the jumja kiosk.
I've noticed she's been making
a lot of visits
to the security office lately.
She has a cousin
who's interested in a career
in law enforcement.
You don't say.
Are you implying that Lysia
Arlin is interested in me?
Ridiculous.
I would have noticed.
Exactly my point.
You must be mistaken.
And how can you be so sure?
Because women don't react
to me in that manner.
Are you saying that you've
never had a female friend?
I consider Major Kira a friend.
That's not what I meant.
I'm talking about...
an intimate friendship.
That's a very personal question.
I'm sorry, but after
seven lifetimes
the impersonal questions
aren't much fun anymore.
Looks like we found
our particle field.
They're omicron particles.
Is that unusual?
Omicron particles
are incredibly rare.
They can only be created
by certain types of
matter/antimatter reactions.
The field seems to be coming
from the second planet
in the system.
Let's go in a little closer.
That's strange.
The particles are concentrated
in one small valley.
Sensors aren't picking up
any life-forms.
The particle field could be
interfering with the sensors.
We better beam down
for a closer look.
I'm still getting
a lot of interference.
The particle field
must be blocking
the tricorder functions.
The interference seems
to be coming from here.
This must be the source
of the field.
It's probably some kind
of matter/antimatter reactor.
Lieutenant, I suggest we leave
before we're discovered.
Give me a minute.
Take all the time you want.
It's about time.
Enter.
Where have you been?
I've been waiting hours...
M-Major.
Uh, I'm sorry, we're closed.
You'll have to come back
in the morning.
Oh, I didn't come here
for a drink.
I thought you'd like to know
your cousin Kono just tried
to come aboard the station.
Kono? Here?
What an unexpected pleasure.
He's gone, Quark.
When we tried to talk to him
he beamed onto a departing
Tellarite freighter.
There must be some mistake.
Why would Kono be coming here?
I was wondering the
same thing myself
so, I did a little checking.
Your cousin's wanted
for robbing a museum
on Cardassia V.
My guess is he thought
someone here would help him
sell the merchandise.
Outrageous.
You have no proof of that.
Quark, get this into that
little twisted brain of yours.
If you thought
you were going to get away
with anything while Odo's
gone, think again.
I'm watching you.
Major?
You make it sound
like you don't like me.
Don't like you?
You collaborated
with the Cardassians.
You cheat your customers
and you're a danger
to this station.
I don't just "not like you."
I despise you.
Sorry I mentioned it.
A-A job?
What do I need a job for?
You're 15 years old.
It's time you took
a little responsibility.
Look, Nog works, doesn't he?
Yeah.
You're almost as old as he is.
When I was your age,
I had a job
and it was
a terrific experience.
All right, I'll talk to Nog
and see if he can get me
a job at Quark's.
Quark's? I was thinking
more along the lines
of you helping out
Chief O'Brien.
Chief O'Brien?
You do like Chief O'Brien,
don't you?
He's okay, but I don't know
anything about engineering.
This is the perfect
opportunity to learn.
Besides, it'll look great
on your application
to Starfleet Academy.
Okay, I'll give it a try.
That's all I ask.
Are we being accused
of some kind of crime?
Have you committed one?
We've just arrived here.
So you keep saying.
If you want,
you can check our ship's logs
and they'll prove it to you.
Logs can be tampered with.
Well, you ought to know that.
After all, you claim to be
a security officer.
I am a security officer,
and I've had enough of this.
If we were guilty, we wouldn't
even be here right now.
I'll prove it.
Computer, one to beam up.
Don't worry,
he'll be right back.
What did I tell you?
Now, that's interesting,
you disappearing like that
because I've got 22 people
who have disappeared
without a trace.
22 missing people?
Did they all disappear
at the same time?
No, it started in the fall.
But the last victim vanished
six hours ago.
Six hours ago
we weren't even in this system.
If you want, you can accompany
us back to our station
and they will verify
everything we've told you.
Do you have any other suspects?
You were my only ones.
I'm not saying
everybody here is perfect.
We have some petty thefts,
an occasional fight, but...
kidnapping, murder?
Nah. Nah, we've never had
anything like
that before.
I see.
So...
have you scanned the area
for signs of transporter
activity?
It was the first thing I tried.
I didn't find anything.
You know, I've been protector
here for almost ten years.
I like to think
I'm pretty good at my job.
People trust me
to solve their problems.
But whoever's behind
these disappearances
is a lot smarter than I am.
I have to admit,
I'm starting to get desperate.
Maybe what you need
is a little help.
Maybe.
Rurigan.
So...
these are the strangers
I heard about?
Shouldn't they be in a cell?
I'm satisfied they have nothing
to do with the disappearances.
In fact, Odo here
is a security officer.
He's going to try to help us.
How do you plan to do that?
I understand your daughter
is the latest victim.
When was the last time
you saw her?
This morning at first meal.
But Taya said she saw her later
in her workroom around midday.
Taya?
My granddaughter.
Colyus, Anetra's gone,
just like the others.
We're never going to find them.
How can you be so sure?
Let's just say I haven't
been proven wrong yet.
I'd like to scan the area again
for transporter activity
in case you missed something.
Go right ahead.
I'm still not getting
a clear reading.
The omicron particles
put out by the reactor
are creating
too much interference.
Oh, must be your equipment.
Our scanners
never give any trouble.
Certain kinds of transporters
leave behind a residual
electrostatic charge.
If we could check
Anetra's workroom?
If you don't mind
I'd like to talk
to your granddaughter.
Well, the last time I saw her,
she was across the square.
I'll take you to her.
Taya?
Don't be afraid, Taya.
This is a friend
of Protector Colyus.
He just wants you to answer
a few questions.
Do I have to?
Not if you don't want to.
But it would help
if I could talk to you
about your mother's
disappearance.
She hasn't disappeared.
She'll be back.
The last time
you saw your mother
did she seem upset
about anything?
Nervous, perhaps, or worried?
She seemed fine.
When will she be coming home?
I don't know, Taya.
Let's go;
it's past your bedtime.
I'd like to ask
a few more questions.
It'll wait till morning.
Chief, here's the new apprentice
we discussed.
Yes, sir.
Welcome aboard.
Well, let's get to work.
I was just about to run
a diagnostic
on the primary system core.
Mr. Sisko...
I almost forgot.
For you.
Thanks, Dad.
It's standard equipment
for all station personnel.
Wait, let me get
this straight, Major.
You want me to spy
on Quark for you?
I wouldn't
call it spying, exactly.
I just thought you might,
you know, keep an eye on him
while Odo's away.
When you're not busy.
Oh, it's no problem, Major.
Then you'll do it?
I look forward to it.
Garak has been lecturing me
on surveillance techniques.
This'll give me a chance
to try some of them out.
Sisko to Kira.
This is Kira.
Major, I thought
you might like to know
we've received word
that Vedek Bareil
is coming aboard the station.
Coming aboard... when?
His ship just arrived
at Docking Bay 12.
I wish you'd given us
a little more notice.
We could have arranged
a formal reception.
Well, that's exactly
what I wanted to avoid.
What brings you to the station?
Prylar Rhit invited me
to speak at the station shrine.
Ah.
But to be honest, I...
I've been looking for
an opportunity to see you.
Really?
I'm honored.
Oh, honored.
Uh, actually, I was hoping
you'd be happy to see me.
Oh, I am.
Very happy.
Hello, Taya.
Remember me?
We met last night.
You wanted to ask me questions.
That's right.
About your mother.
I understand you were
the last one to see her.
I guess.
What happened to your face?
Nothing happened to my face.
I'm a shape-shifter.
I just don't do faces very well.
I have the ability
to change my shape
to look like other things.
You mean, you're a changeling?
That's right.
There's no such thing
as changelings.
They're make-believe.
Everyone knows that.
Well, I'm not make-believe.
All right, then let me see
you change into something.
Maybe later.
Right now, I feel like talking.
If I were a changeling,
I'd change shapes all the time.
Everyone would want
to be my friend.
Ha. I wish it were that easy.
Why wouldn't it be?
When I was younger
people were always asking me
to change shape for them.
They'd pretend to be my friends,
but all they wanted
was to see me become a chair
or an animal.
None of them ever
really cared about me.
Maybe they were scared of you.
Some of them probably were.
I'm not afraid of you.
I'm glad to hear that.
Were your parents
changelings, too?
I never knew my parents.
I've been looking for them
for a long time.
My father died when I was four.
I don't remember him very well.
The last time I saw my mother
she was in her workroom
making pottery.
When I went to get her for
the midday meal, she was gone.
How did she act
when you last saw her?
Happy.
She was making a vase
for Mr. Depnen, the baker.
He really likes my mom
so he always saves us
the best loaf of greenbread.
Has your mother ever gone
anywhere before?
A trip, vacation?
We don't go on trips.
Never?
No, we never leave the valley.
Why not?
Nobody ever leaves the valley.
Everything we need
is right here.
I see.
My mother's never coming back,
is she?
Why do you say that?
It's what my grandfather
told me.
Taya, I don't know
where your mother is
but I promise you,
I'm going to do everything I can
to find her
and bring her back to you.
Okay, one more time.
These are all isolinear rods.
The ones with the white labels
contain data
relating to the engineering
systems controls
the red-labeled ones
are for library
and information storage
and the blue ones are?
I'm never going to get this.
Give yourself some time.
I didn't get a handle
on this stuff
until almost a year
after I joined Starfleet.
I mean, it's not
like you're going off
to the Academy tomorrow, is it?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's just that,
why does everyone assume
that I'm going to the Academy?
Well, you want to go,
don't you?
Not really.
Does your father know?
He wouldn't understand.
I know how you feel.
You know what my father
wanted me to be?
A musician.
It's true.
I was supposed to be
a cello player.
He made me practice
every day.
I got to be pretty good.
When I was 17, he sent
a recorded audition
to the Aldebaran Music Academy.
What happened?
Oh, I got in.
It was the happiest day
of his life.
I didn't know how to tell him
I didn't want to go.
So, two days before
I was due to leave
I went into town
and signed up for Starfleet.
What did your dad do?
Oh, he was furious.
But once he calmed down
a little
he saw how much
I wanted to join.
Nowadays when I go home,
he introduces me as...
"My son
Senior Chief Specialist
Miles Edward O'Brien."
The point is, you've got
to live your own life.
I don't want
to disappoint my dad.
Hey, your dad's not a bad guy.
He'll come around.
Just give him some time.
So...
What did you think?
Of your speech?
Mm-hmm.
I liked everything about it...
except the content.
You disagree
with my interpretation
of the Eighth Prophecy?
"Disagree" is a bit
of an understatement.
"Passionately disagree"
is more like it.
The way you have
of taking a prophecy
and showing that it can mean
exactly the opposite
of the accepted
interpretation is...
Oh, it's brilliant.
Uh... insightful.
Infuriating.
Maybe we should talk
about something else.
Like what?
Well, the Ilvian
katterpod crop maybe?
Or, uh...
the new nature preserve
in Hedrikspool Province.
Hmm? No?
Maybe the standings in
the Springball Championship.
You follow springball?
Religiously... if you'll
pardon the expression.
I even used to play a little.
Me, too.
I had Chief O'Brien design
a springball holosuite program.
Really?
Let's go.
You want to play springball?
Why not?
Well, unless you have
a more pressing engagement.
Not that I can think of.
Good.
I could use the practice.
From what I understand, you...
helped found this colony.
That's right.
I'm the oldest one left.
This colony must be
very important to you.
You helped found it,
you raised a family here.
I'm very proud
of what we've accomplished.
Then explain something to me.
This colony is undergoing
a serious crisis.
Your daughter is
among the missing.
Yet, you hardly seem concerned.
There is nothing I can do
to change things.
I wish there were.
Now, is there anything else,
or can I go?
Are you sure you're all right?
Why wouldn't I be?
You seem to be
in a great deal of pain.
Why do you say that?
I can see it in your eyes.
Perhaps you'd like
to sit here for a moment
and rest.
Well, it wouldn't do much good.
You see, I'm dying.
I'm sorry.
Well, I've had a good life.
No regrets.
I wish I could see
my daughter once again.
Now, if there are
no more questions...
Actually, there is one thing
I've been wondering.
How come...
no one ever leaves the village?
I haven't met anyone yet
who's ever been
outside this valley.
Any idea why?
I suppose it's because
people around here
don't like to travel.
After all,
there's no place to go.
How can you be so sure?
Have you ever left the valley?
Now that you mention it...
no.
When I asked Colyus
if he searched
outside the valley
for the missing people,
he looked surprised
as if he'd never
thought of it before.
I find that very peculiar.
Where I come from
we would have searched
the entire countryside.
Yes.
I suppose Colyus thought
there was no point to it.
But I guarantee you...
there are no missing people
out there.
You're sure of that?
Absolutely.
And then the great Minra said
to the evil changeling
"Maybe you can turn
into a mountain
"or a Ghergher Beast
or a tornado
"but those are big things,
and big things are easy.
"I bet you can't turn
into something small
like a loaf of greenbread."
And the changeling
said, "Yes, I can"
and he did.
Then do you know what happened?
The great Minra gobbled him up.
How'd you know that?
The changeling in your story
wasn't very smart.
Could you turn into a loaf
of greenbread?
I suppose I could.
Show me.
And let you gobble me up?
I don't think so.
See that tree?
Sometimes we go there to play.
That's the furthest I've
ever been from the village.
Wait here.
But I want to come see, too.
Please, do as I say.
Lieutenant,
would you come with me?
I'm still not reading
any other life-forms
and no indication
of any power source.
Did you see that?
It, it just vanished!
It happened just
as we passed those bushes.
Taya.
Taya, don't come any closer!
But I brought you
some Harrid berries.
Odo says you know what happened
to the missing villagers.
I think I do.
It's a little
complicated to explain.
It'd probably be easier
if I showed you.
May I have your cloak?
My... my cloak?
Please.
Well...
Thank you.
Now, stand back.
I'm waiting.
This may take a minute.
I don't want to make a mistake.
That was my favorite cloak!
Please, stay where you are.
Are you saying
somebody used our reactor
to transport the victims away?
No.
It's not a transporter.
It's a holographic projector.
It creates an omicron
particle field
and then manipulates the field
to form physical objects
like your cloak.
Well, what does this have to do
with the missing people?
The people are made up
of omicron particles, too.
You mean they're...
holograms?
I'm afraid so.
You see, the component
that controls
the particle field...
it's breaking down
and that's why people
are disappearing.
Well, that's ridiculous!
Some of the victims
were my friends.
One of them is my nephew.
If I'm right
everyone and everything
in this village
is a holographic projection.
And I thought I was desperate
to find an answer.
Listen to her, Colyus.
I know this is difficult
to accept.
It's going to take a whole lot
more than a vanishing cloak
to make me believe
I'm some kind of hologram.
I'd be skeptical,
too, if I were you
but we have further proof.
What kind of proof?
The holographic field ends
just outside this valley,
and earlier today
Taya tried to reach
past the edge
and her arm disappeared.
Is she all right?
She's fine.
Her arm re-materialized
as soon as she pulled it
back inside.
Where exactly did this happen?
We could show you if you'd like.
I think you'd better.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
I should have seen it coming.
Where did you learn
to play like that?
My brothers and I used to play
at the Singha refugee camp.
There wasn't much else to do.
Yeah, I was at Relliketh.
And, uh, now...
uh, here we are.
Well, uh, uh, that, uh...
that was delicious.
Well...
thank the replicator.
Here, let me help.
That's not necessary.
Your shoulder...
Never felt better.
Maybe I do need
some help after all.
I'll have to remember
to thank Prylar Rhit
for inviting you here.
You'd better tell him soon.
Prylar Rhit...
is going to be
returning to Bajor.
It appears he fancies
himself something...
of a dabo player.
Oh... really?
Mm-hmm.
He's run up a...
sizable gambling debt.
It's caused...
quite a scandal
in the Vedek assembly.
Let me get this straight...
the man who invited you
here to the station...
owes money... to Quark?
To who?
The little troll
who runs the dabo tables?
I got to go.
But why?
I need to talk to Prylar Rhit.
I think I know the real reason
he invited you here.
People, please!
Please!
Quiet!
Calm down!
Calm down, everybody.
We have to make a decision here.
Colyus, you should be out
looking for my wife
and all the others
who are missing!
Not wasting time
listening to these strangers
and their lies.
You all witnessed what happened
when they brought us
to the edge of the field.
Merruk, we both saw
your hand disappear.
It could have been a trick.
It wasn't a trick.
Then how come we've never
learned of this before?
Because none of you ever tried
to leave the valley.
It's possible
we were programmed not to leave
so that we wouldn't
learn the truth.
Now, we have
to shut down the system.
If we don't fix it soon,
the whole village will disappear
Dax...
you said if you can
fix the machine
you might be able to bring back
the missing people.
We hope so.
What if you turn off
the projector
and you can't get it back on?
Then this village
will cease to exist.
The system's
only a few months away
from complete failure anyway.
At least this way, we have
a chance to save you.
Grandfather, please.
Let her try.
What do you think?
Well, we can't go on like this.
I guess we should
let her shut it down.
Are there any objections?
Then it's settled.
I can't wait to see my mother.
Your face isn't so scary...
once you get used to it.
Thank you, Taya.
All right, here we go.
Odo...
Don't look so surprised.
I'm as real as you are.
I was happy living
on Yadera Prime.
That is,
until the Dominion took over
and changed
our whole way of life.
And I realized one morning
that I didn't really
belong there anymore.
So I came here.
And I used a hologenerator
to recreate all the things
that I'd lost.
I have lived here in my village
for nearly 30 years.
And I've watched
the people marry...
have children...
grow old...
and sometimes I even forgot
that they were holograms.
But it's over.
It's over.
And I would appreciate it
if you'd take me back
to Yadera Prime.
But what about the villagers?
What about your granddaughter?
She's not real.
Technically,
I suppose you're right.
Maybe, by our definition,
Taya's not real.
Her memories are stored
in a computer.
Her body is made up
of omicron particles.
But who's to say
that our definition of life
is the only valid one?
I'm sure if you asked her,
she'd say she was real.
She thinks, she feels.
She only seems to.
It's all an illusion.
An illusion I created.
Well, you said you created
the village 30 years ago.
Taya's only ten.
I designed the program
so the villagers
could have children
if they wanted to.
Then Taya's personality
is a combination
of her parents' personalities.
Just like a real child.
You had nothing to do with it.
But she's still a hologram.
Maybe...
but I saw the way
you held her hand
when she was sad.
I saw the way
you tried to comfort her
when she was frightened.
I... I didn't want her
to get hurt.
If she's not real,
what does it matter?
It matters.
It matters to me.
Why should it matter to you
if a hologram cries?
Because I love her.
And she loves you.
Don't you see?
She's real to you.
And she's real to me, too.
They're all real.
And you can't
turn your back on them now.
Jake, how was work?
Okay.
It's kind of fun
working with Chief O'Brien.
But it would be better
if I knew what I was doing.
You'll get there.
I guess so.
I'm glad you decided
to stick with it.
Yeah.
Dad...
I don't want to join Starfleet.
Since when?
S-since forever.
Starfleet is too much like you.
I need to find what's me.
Does that make any sense?
Perfect sense.
It does?
It's your life, Jake.
You have to choose your own way.
There is only one thing
I want from you.
Find something you love
then do it the best you can.
I'll try.
Good.
Then you'll make
the old man proud.
I'd better go study.
I'm still trying to figure out
those isolinear rods.
Hello, Quark.
Major.
To what do I owe this
unexpected pleasure?
I just thought
I'd let you know...
we caught your cousin
trying to slip back
onto this station
and guess what we
confiscated from him?
Bone carvings.
Stolen from a museum
on Cardassia V.
I always knew
Kono was no good.
I only wish
we could have caught
the two of you together.
Life is full
of disappointments.
By the way,
Prylar Rhit tells me
that you encouraged him
to invite Bareil
onto this station.
That a crime?
Not at all.
I just wanted to thank you.
I found him very...
diverting.
Not diverting enough.
All right,
nothing to do now
but reactivate the system
and see what happens.
Wait.
Lieutenant, I'd like
to ask a favor.
If this works,
please don't tell the others
that I'm... not like them.
I don't want to be treated
any differently than before.
Of course.
Mother?
Mother!
Well, you did it.
We upgraded the
system's memory core
and realigned
the field generators.
I don't think
you'll have to worry
about anyone disappearing now.
We just have to get used
to the fact
that we're holograms.
We're alive and we have
our families back.
That's the only
thing that counts.
I wonder who created all this?
Whoever it was,
did a fine job.
They did, didn't they?
Well, it was good
working with you, Odo.
Next time you're
on this side of the galaxy
I hope you come by
and see us.
I would like that.
We don't get
that many visitors.
Odo.
My mother's back.
I'm glad.
You're leaving.
I'm afraid so.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you, too.
Thank you for bringing
my mother back.
I hope you find
your parents, too.
Thank you, Taya.
So do I.
Taya...
Computer, two to beam up.