KIRA:
Definitely Cardassian.
And in trouble.
Its engines are
completely disabled.
Open a hailing frequency.
This is Commander Sisko
of Deep Space 9.
Do you need assistance?
DAX:
They're not answering.
Their life-support systems
are operating
on reserve power.
Better lock on
a tractor beam
and pull them
into Cargo Bay 7.
Tell Mr. O'Brien
to meet me there.
Welcome aboard.
I'm Benjamin Sisko
Commander of
Deep Space 9.
My Chief
of Operations,
Miles O'Brien.
Do any of you need
medical assistance?
I think we're all
fine, considering.
I'm Professor
Natima Lang.
These are two
of my students
Rekelen and Hogue.
And what happened
to your ship?
We were caught
in a meteor storm.
I'm a decent teacher,
but I'm afraid
I'm not much
of a shuttle pilot.
Do you think you'll be
able to repair our ship?
I'll have
to take a look.
Excuse me.
We'd like to be on our way
as soon as possible.
We know having Cardassians
on a Bajoran station
may cause trouble.
That's the last
thing we want.
If anyone can
fix your ship
it is Mr. O'Brien.
In the meantime,
you're welcome to stay here.
If you stick
to the Promenade,
I'm sure there
won't be any trouble.
BASHIR:
Wait, wait,
wait a second.
Are you telling me
that you agreed
with General Yiri's
decision
to execute
his brother?
Of course, I agree.
Yiri's brother was a traitor
to the Trelonian government.
The evidence
is all circumstantial.
It all comes down
to a question of loyalty.
My dear Doctor.
Yiri had to choose between
protecting his brother
and protecting the state.
He chose the state.
As would I, every time.
Well, I suppose that's
one way of looking at it.
But then again,
before you can be
loyal to another,
you must be loyal to yourself.
And who can we thank for those
misguided words of wisdom?
Sarek of Vulcan?
Actually, it was
Bashir of Earth.
With sentiments like those,
you wouldn't last
for five seconds on Cardassia.
Would you?
Fishing again, Doctor?
Well, assuming
you're not a spy...
Assuming?
Then maybe you're an outcast.
Or maybe I'm an outcast spy.
Ah, how could you be both?
I never said I was either.
( sighs )
I heard an interesting
rumor today.
Only one?
I started at least 12.
Rumor has it
that you've managed
to get your hands
on a small cloaking device.
And you believe
everything you hear?
When it's about you, yes.
According to Bajoran law,
such a device would
be highly illegal.
If I had one,
which I don't.
I didn't expect
you to admit it.
I'm simply serving notice.
You try to sell it,
and I'll see to it
that you spend
the next 50 years
digging trenches
in a penal colony.
I told you.
You have nothing
to worry about.
( yells )
Excuse me!
Hey!
Out of my way!
Excuse me!
Natima!
Quark!
I knew you'd come--
I told you never
to speak to me again.
( panting )
Are you all right?
All right?
This is the happiest
day of my life.
Natima, wait!
At least let me buy you
and your friends a drink.
I could make you
a Samarian Sunset.
I don't drink
Samarian Sunsets anymore.
Why not?
Because they
remind me of you.
Is this Ferengi
bothering you?
This Ferengi happens to be
Natima's old
and cherished friend.
Who are you?
These are my students.
Students?
You don't say?
I'd love to sit in
on one of your classes.
What do you teach?
Political ethics.
Her teachings will change
the future of Cardassia.
That's enough, Rekelen.
Not at all.
I want to hear more.
I always knew Natima
was destined for greatness.
Quark.
Just one drink.
It'll be like old times.
It'll never be
like old times.
You're right--
it'll be better.
I'll be right back
with refreshments.
ODO:
Your hands
are shaking.
So, how well does
this woman know you?
Just enough
to dislike you
or well enough
to really hate you?
She used to work
here on the station.
She was a correspondent
with the Cardassian
Information Service.
It was before your time.
So, which is it--
dislike or hate?
It's none
of your business.
But if you have to know,
I was the love of her life.
Hmph! Must have been some life.
What about our drinks?
You want a drink?
The bar's right
over there.
Go ahead.
Your Samarian Sunset.
I said I didn't
drink these anymore.
Because they remind you of me.
But since I'm here anyway,
you may as well enjoy yourself.
Besides, it's on the house.
You know,
you're as beautiful as ever.
And you're as big
a liar as ever.
You see, just like old times.
I've missed you, Natima,
and that's no lie.
You seem to have kept busy.
Oh, yes,
I'm very successful.
But as the 223rd Rule
of Acquisition says--
Please! I haven't heard
a Rule of Acquisition
in seven years
and I don't want
to hear one now.
So... how long you going
to be on the station?
Thank you for another
enjoyable lunch, Doctor.
I didn't think
there were any Cardassians
left on this station.
He's the only one.
What do we do now?
Is something wrong?
We have to leave
as soon as possible.
Goodbye, Quark.
Thanks for the drink.
But... you didn't touch it.
SISKO:
How are your
repairs coming?
The damage is more extensive
than I thought.
They were lucky
to escape the attack.
The attack?
They weren't
in any meteor storm.
They were hit
by Cardassian disrupters.
KIRA:
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
Why would Cardassians
fire on other
Cardassians?
Maybe you
should ask her.
Commander, I hate
to be an imposition
but I need my ship.
That's not possible.
Mr. O'Brien
is still working on it.
Your ship sustained more damage
than we originally thought.
In fact--
You suspect that our ship
was damaged
by Cardassian weapons.
You're right, of course.
Professor.
It's all right, Hogue.
I should have told them
the truth in the first place.
Then why didn't you?
Because Cardassians
don't involve outsiders
in their internal politics,
especially Bajorans.
Being shot at by your own people
goes a little beyond politics.
We take our politics
very seriously.
Commander, if I don't
get my students to safety,
they're going to be killed.
And if they die,
the future of Cardassia
may die with them.
There are some who believe
that the future of Cardassia
should not remain
in the hands of the military.
And you're among them?
Yes, we are.
Rekelen and Hogue
are two
of the most important leaders
of our movement.
Which makes you fugitives.
The military is afraid
to let us speak our minds.
REKELEN:
They've already tried
to kill us once.
They're sure to try again.
Which is why I have to get
them off this station
as soon as possible.
I'll dispatch additional work
crews to help repair your ship.
We saw another Cardassian
aboard the station, in the bar.
Garak.
He saw you?
I'm certain of it.
Well, then,
we may have a problem.
Mr. Garak is a bit
of a mystery to us.
I'll assign you
some guest quarters.
You'll be safe there
until your ship is ready.
We appreciate
your assistance, Commander.
Ah, Mr. Quark.
This is a surprise.
I don't believe
you've ever been
in my establishment before.
You usually don't
frequent mine either.
Though I did see
you in there today.
Ah, the replimat
was a little crowded.
So, what brings
you here now?
Oh, I just wanted to see
what you were offering.
Ooh, what do you
get for that?
Ah ha...
17 strips of latinum.
Whoo, I'll tell you what--
I'll give you 20.
Twenty!
How uncharacteristically
generous for a Ferengi.
Just one businessman
trying to help out another.
I figure we have
to stick together.
Well, this is the latest
style on my home world.
Do you like it?
I'm no expert
in Cardassian fashions.
What do you think?
Well, I don't know.
It's been so long since
I've had a Cardassian customer.
Then you're in luck.
There's some on board
the station right now.
Now, that you mention it,
I think your lady friend might
find this style very appealing.
You're old friends, aren't you?
You're very perceptive...
for a Cardassian.
It would have been hard to miss
the way you were looking at her.
Personally, I find this style
a bit too radical.
But your friend seems the sort
who appreciates
that kind of thing.
Different tastes
for different people.
Nothing wrong with that.
Is there?
Oh, you'd be surprised
how detrimental
a poor choice of fashion can be.
Take this dress.
It may be all the rage now,
but in a very short time,
it can become tiresome--
an affront
to the eyes.
Certain people might even
think it's objectionable.
And then...
nothing but rags.
I see.
Mr. Quark, might I offer
you some free advice?
As long as I'm under no
obligation to follow it.
I've been in this
business a long time
and I know
there's nothing worse
than following
the wrong trend.
Now, you're
a smart fellow,
with your own inimitable
sense of style.
Perhaps you should mention this
to your lady friend.
I'd hate to see her
fall victim to fashion.
Would you like to explain that?
She's chosen
to associate herself
with some rather
flamboyant companions.
It would be a tragedy
if she got in the way
when her friends
go out of fashion.
If anyone tries
to harm her,
they're going
to have to deal with me.
And what are
you going to do?
Shortchange them
at the dabo table?
I think I'll buy
this dress after all.
Ah.
See that it's mended.
What is it you want from me?
I know you're in trouble.
I want to help you.
I don't want your help.
I owe you.
You saved my life.
If you'd turned me over
to the authorities,
I would have been executed.
I admired your courage.
It was a brave thing
you were doing
selling food
to the Bajorans.
I thought you
were a man of honor.
I'm a Ferengi.
You should have known better.
You're right. I should have.
Instead...
Can't you even say it?
I can't even think it.
Okay, I'll say
it for you.
We fell in love,
and that month we spent together
was the best time of our lives
and you know it.
I think you're confusing
lust with love.
I admit,
I'm capable of that,
but not this time.
I loved you, Natima.
Then how could you
have betrayed me?
I didn't betray you.
Don't lie to me, Quark.
I know better.
You used
my personal access codes
to authorize payments
for goods you never provided.
So, I took a little money
from the Cardassian
Communication Service.
They could afford it.
You stole that money.
I saw a chance for profit,
and I took it.
Maybe that was wrong.
I don't know.
But what I really regret
is betraying your trust.
That was the worst mistake
of my life.
And you'd do it
again in a second.
I believed in you, Quark,
but you were using me
like you use everyone.
For profit.
Then let me make it up to you.
Let me help you.
I ask for nothing
in return.
Nothing?
Except that you stay
with me forever.
I can't stay here.
My students need me.
Listen to me, Natima.
You can't leave me, not now.
If you don't stay with me,
I'll have to follow you.
And I will, wherever you go,
until you agree to take me back.
You don't even know
who I am anymore.
I'm part
of the Cardassian Underground.
Following me will
only get you killed.
I'll take that chance.
What about the bar?
I don't care
about the bar.
I'll turn it over to Rom.
He'll run it into the ground in
a month, but it doesn't matter.
I have to be with you.
It won't work, Quark.
You say you'd do
anything for me.
Maybe right now,
you even believe it.
But I know better.
In the end,
you'd only care about yourself.
But I love you.
I don't love you.
Uh-huh, now which one
of us is lying?
You better go.
All right...
but if there's
anything you need,
anything at all,
I'll be waiting.
It'll be a long wait.
Professor Lang's ship
should be ready to go
in about an hour, Commander.
Good. I'll let her know.
We have a Cardassian warship
approaching, fast.
On screen.
Hail them,
Lieutenant.
DAX:
No response.
They're taking up
an attack posture.
They're ignoring us.
They're powering up
their forward disrupters.
Shields.
Shields up.
Lock on phasers
and photon torpedoes.
Prepare to fire,
if necessary.
GARAK:
Commander...
I think we should talk.
All right, Garak,
do you mind telling me
why a Cardassian warship
is threatening my station?
No one is threatening you.
The Central Command
merely wants to make sure
they have your
undivided attention.
Well, they have it.
I assume this has
something to do
with Professor Lang
and her students?
"Students" is a rather
benign term for them.
"Terrorists" would
be more accurate.
The Cardassian government
would very much like
Hogue and Rekelen
returned home immediately.
They haven't committed
any crimes here.
As long as they're
on my station,
they're free to do
whatever they want.
This is all very
embarrassing, Commander.
The Central Command
would hate to see
the Federation pulled
into such an insignificant
and purely internal affair.
I'd hardly call
it insignificant.
Judging by the behavior
of the ship out there,
it appears the Central Command
considers Hogue and Rekelen
to be extremely dangerous.
Not at all.
Annoying perhaps,
inconvenient maybe,
but dangerous?
Hardly.
And if they were dangerous,
would the Central Command
entrust the situation to me,
a simple tailor?
Which only confirms what
I have suspected all along.
You, Mr. Garak,
are no simple tailor.
( laughing )
Oh, really, Commander.
That's another
discussion entirely.
All you really need
to know right now
is that the return of Hogue and
Rekelen is in the best interest
of the Cardassian Empire.
Or at least in the best interest
of the Cardassian military.
Is there a difference?
Do you
really expect
a Bajoran station
under Federation command
to turn over Cardassian
political refugees
on your say-so?
The ultimate decision
is, of course, yours.
I am simply relaying a message.
Then relay this.
Tell the Central Command
if anyone attempts to take
Hogue and Rekelen by force,
I will respond in kind.
Am I clear, Mr. Garak?
Absolutely.
Thank you for your time.
Oh, and if you'd like,
stop by the shop one day.
I have a number of suits
that would look
quite flattering on you.
Here you go.
Two mugs of kanar,
on the house.
We didn't order these.
They're the drinks
I promised you
the first time
you came in here.
Sorry they
took so long
but things have been
a little hectic.
Do you mind?
I'm afraid
that we do.
Professor Lang told us
you couldn't be trusted.
Ooh, you Cardassians
do hold grudges.
Seven years ago,
Natima and I had some
little, silly lover's quarrel
and... well, all I can say is
I'm willing to let
bygones be bygones.
But Professor Lang isn't.
I have to say,
I find your loyalty to her
extremely... touching.
There is nothing that
we wouldn't do for her
and if she says that
we're not to talk to you
we don't talk to you.
I understand.
She's your teacher.
You're her students.
You have
to listen to her.
So, if you don't
want to talk to the only person
who can get you off
this station in one piece,
that's fine with me.
Wait.
You say you can
help us get away?
It's possible.
How?
One second.
The station Security Chief's
a shape-shifter.
You can never be too careful.
I take it you know
what a, um, cloaking device is.
Well, I have one.
It's not in the best
of condition,
but it'll work
for about 15 minutes.
Long enough to get you
away from here.
Sounds expensive.
We don't have
much latinum.
What we do h-have...
is yours.
Exactly how much latinum
are we talking about--
No, forget I said that.
I don't want your money.
Consider the cloaking device...
a gift.
I'm surprised.
Ferengis aren't known
for their generosity.
Oh, we are a deeply
misunderstood race.
You may have
saved our lives.
Our movement owes you
a debt of gratitude.
And I know exactly
how you can repay me.
You have to convince Natima
to stay here.
The Professor
will never agree
to stay behind.
No Natima, no cloaking device,
and no way off this station.
She won't do it.
You'll have
to talk her into it.
After all, you're the ones
the Cardassians are after.
He's right.
She shouldn't have to risk
her life for our crimes.
I suppose we
could ask her.
Don't ask her; tell her.
We will.
We'll do our best.
I'm sure you will.
I shudder to think
what would happen
if the military
got its hands on you.
Meet us at our quarters
in an hour.
I'll be there.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Where are
Rekelen and Hogue?
They're waiting
at the ship.
Perfect.
I know my quarters may seem
a little crowded at first,
but tomorrow morning,
I'll put in a request
for something bigger.
That won't be necessary.
All right.
If you want your
own quarters
to start out with,
I can arrange that, too.
I mean, I'm not staying.
Now, hold on.
Your students and I
have an agreement.
They get the
cloaking device
and you stay with me.
That way, everyone's happy.
Quark, you say
you love me.
Then give me
that cloaking device
and let me be on my way.
And let you disappear
out of my life again?
I'm not part of your life.
But you are.
You always have been.
Don't you understand?
Since you left me,
not a day goes by
that I don't
regret what I did.
And now you're asking
me to lose you again!
You lost me
a long time ago.
All right, then say it.
Let me hear you say
there isn't a spark
of love left in you.
There isn't a spark
of love left in me.
I heard that.
What?
You hesitated.
Admit it,
you still care.
Quark, I don't
have time for this.
Give me that
cloaking device.
I can't.
I won't let you go.
Quark.
I didn't want to have
to get it this way,
but I need that device.
Give it to me.
Now.
Or what?
You'll shoot me?
If I have to.
Then go ahead
and shoot.
Quark, Quark?
Are you all right?
You shot me.
Well, I didn't mean to.
It was an accident.
I've never fired
a phaser before.
I barely touched
the trigger.
Careful.
( groans )
It hurts?
Oh, she wants
to know if it hurts.
Of course it hurts.
It's supposed
to hurt, it's a phaser.
I made sure it was
on the first setting.
How considerate
of you.
Should I get a doctor?
It's okay.
Maybe if
you rub it.
Oh, Quark, I'm sorry.
Really?
Yes, for everything,
for all those horrible things
I said.
You really
didn't mean them?
I love you, Quark.
I've always loved you,
even when I hated you.
Natima.
I've missed you.
I missed you so much.
Being with you was
the happiest time of my life.
And now we're
together again
and we have the rest
of our lives to be happy.
I wish it was that easy.
But it can be,
if you let it.
I'm not the same person
I was seven years ago.
I have responsibilities.
I'll share them with you.
The movement
is my life now.
I don't have time
for anything else.
We'll make the time.
You're a woman, Natima.
Believe me, I know.
And it's not right
for you to be alone.
I-I'm not alone, I...
I have my students...
my dreams for
a better Cardassia.
But are dreams enough?
Can dreams make
you laugh?
Can dreams hold
you close at night?
No!
But my life demands
I make certain sacrifices.
And you've made them,
but it doesn't mean
you can't be happy.
We did have fun together,
didn't we?
Remember the day I installed
my first holosuite?
I'd never been
in one before.
I still have that program,
the Picnic on Rhymus Major.
Two suns in the sky.
The sound of the waterfalls.
The whisper of flitterbird
wings over our heads.
You painted my face with honey.
And a Mordian butterfly
landed on your nose.
got stuck on my nose.
His wings were beating
almost as fast as my heart.
Those were good times.
The best.
And we can have them back again.
I'll give the cloaking
device to your students.
Once they're gone,
you'll be safe and
we can be together.
I can't just abandon them.
They need me.
I need you.
Listen to me, Natima,
you've done enough
for the movement.
You lit the match.
Let them carry the torch.
Or are you saying
that the movement
won't survive without you?
Of course it will.
Then let it,
and let us have the
happiness we deserve.
You really do love me,
don't you?
With all that
I am, Natima...
forever.
Will you stay?
Yes, Quark, I'll stay.
You don't know
how I've waited
to hear you say that.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Professor Lang.
Not now, Odo.
Can't you see
we're busy?
I apologize
for the interruption
but I'm afraid, madam,
that you are under arrest.
I'm what?
On what charge?
Commander Sisko
will explain.
I'm truly sorry.
Now, hold on...
Quark, it's all right.
Commander, would
you please explain
what we're
doing here?
I'm afraid all of you
are to be turned over
to the Cardassian government.
You can't do that.
I wish I didn't have to,
but Cardassia
has offered to release
half a dozen Bajoran prisoners
in exchange for you.
And you've
agreed to this?
The Bajoran Provisional
Government has agreed to it.
A Cardassian transport
will deliver the Bajoran
prisoners within five hours.
Commander,
you have no idea
what they'll do to us.
We're the ones
they're after.
At least let
Professor Lang go.
SISKO:
I'd like
nothing better,
but the Provisional
Government
has ordered you all
to be turned over.
I'm fighting this
every way I can.
I'm not ready
to give up yet.
But in the end,
this is a Bajoran station
and I have to abide
by their decision
no matter how much
I disagree with it.
How the mighty
have fallen.
Toran?
It's Gul Toran now.
They made you a Gul.
I didn't realize the situation
on Cardassia had gotten
so desperate.
I find your bitterness
extremely gratifying.
I'm glad to see
that you're adjusting
so poorly to exile.
Actually, I'm finding
my time here quite illuminating.
Then I don't suppose
you'd be interested
in going home again?
Am I to be rewarded
for informing
the Central Command
about the presence of Hogue
and Rekelen on the station?
Perhaps.
But only after
you see to it
that they don't leave
this station alive.
But I suggested
a prisoner exchange
and the
Central Command agreed.
I convinced them otherwise.
And they listened to you?
My voice is less tarnished
than yours.
Kill them, and all you do
is create martyrs.
You overestimate
their importance.
And how do you
propose to arrange
this unfortunate incident?
I'm sure you'll think
of something.
You always did
in the past.
Don't you see?
Lang's death
will benefit us both.
Unless, of course,
you intend to spend the rest
of your life as a tailor.
I see your point.
I knew you would.
( door opening )
Odo, we have to talk.
I'm busy.
Come back later.
Later will be too late.
I, The Jury,
by Mickey Spillane?
Chief O'Brien
loaned it to me.
This better be
important, Quark.
It is.
Odo, you have to let Natima
and her students go.
Do I?
Those students could be
the key to a new Cardassia,
a Cardassia free
of military rule and oppression.
Now, since when
have you become
so interested in
Cardassian politics?
A freer, more open society
on Cardassia
would benefit
this entire sector
and it would be great
for business.
So, wanting me to free
Natima and those students
is strictly a financial
consideration on your part?
Now, Odo...
don't allow my greed
to keep you from doing
the right thing.
I know you better
than you think, Quark.
This isn't about Cardassia,
and for once, it's not
even about profit.
This is about
Professor Lang.
You're right. It is.
Her life is in jeopardy
as long as Rekelen and Hogue
are on the station.
Now, why didn't you
tell me that before?
What was I supposed to say?
That I love her?
That I would do
anything for her?
That without her,
my life would be meaningless.
Sure, I could say those things,
but what good would it do?
How could I expect you
to understand?
You've never had
those feelings.
You don't know what it means
to really care
about another person.
You've never been in love.
You've got all the emotions
of a stone.
No offense.
Go on.
Listen to me, Odo.
You do this for me,
and I promise you
there'll be no more secrets
between us.
I'll tell you about
every underhanded deal,
every lying scheme,
every dirty trick
my brother Rom's involved in.
Well... since you put it
that way,
I'm not interested.
Okay.
Okay, let me put it another way.
Do it for me.
For you?
That's right.
For all the years
we've known each other
for everything we've
been through together.
You say you know me
better than anyone else.
Well, I know you.
Sure, sometimes
we're on opposite sides,
but that doesn't mean
that we aren't close.
I never told
you this, Odo,
but I consider you
as dear to me
as my brother.
( derisive snort )
And I've seen how well
you treat him.
Odo...
look at me.
( sighs )
Look at me.
I'm on my knees.
I'm begging you.
I don't care why you do it.
Pick any reason you want.
But please let Natima
and the others go.
All right, I'll do it.
You will?
But not for you.
Turning Hogue and Rekelen over
to the Cardassians
would mean their deaths.
I've read their files,
and nothing they've done
warrants that kind
of punishment.
I'll free them, Quark,
but only in the name of justice.
Justice.
That was going to be
my next suggestion.
So, you're not really
doing this for me?
That's right.
Then I don't owe you
a thing. Thank you!
You'll never know
how much this means to me.
Let go.
Sorry.
Uh... now, um,
let's hurry
before you change your mind.
One question.
How do you expect
Rekelen and Hogue
to get past
that war ship?
Uh...
Uh-huh...
I knew you had
a cloaking device.
I always said you were
too smart for me, Odo.
NATIMA:
Quark,
what are
you doing here?
Getting you out.
Thank you.
Good luck.
I've installed
the cloaking device
in the central
engine core.
You can activate
it from the Bridge
as soon as the mooring
clamps are released.
Then, I suggest you take
your ship to warp eight
and don't look back.
Now, please,
make your good-byes brief.
Oh, what's the rush?
You've betrayed us.
No.
Don't-- I'd hate to ruin
such a... nice suit.
Why are you doing this?
Oh, exile tends to wear
a bit thin after a while
even with surroundings
as pleasant as these.
Fine, take them,
but leave Natima alone.
Quark!
No, he's right.
We're the fugitives,
not you.
You see, they agree with me.
Unfortunately,
it's not their decision to make,
nor mine.
Professor Lang, however minor
her role in this matter,
has come to the attention
of the Central Command.
Do you think killing us
will change anything?
Cardassia is slipping out
of the hands of the military
and nothing you do
will prevent it.
Madam, I am not here
to debate you.
Garak, if you harm
these people, I'll see to it
that Commander Sisko
prosecutes you
to the fullest extent
of the law.
Which brings up another issue.
Quark, things would have gone
much easier
if you'd taken my advice
and not gotten involved
with these people.
I was already involved.
I know.
A pity, really.
Personally,
I rather like you, Quark.
You mean, you're going
to shoot me, too?
Before I became a tailor,
I lived by a simple motto:
Never let sentiment
get in the way of your work.
A bit of a clich,
but true, nonetheless.
I'll keep that in mind.
Well, then, although I admit
it's against my better judgment,
I'm afraid I must carry out the
verdict of the Central Command.
But you admit
that they're wrong.
Why don't you stand up
for what you believe in?
TORAN:
More to the point,
what do you believe in, Garak?
What are you doing here, Toran?
Making sure that you
carry out your assignment.
I suspected that two years
living among the Bajorans
would make you soft.
I see
that I was right.
You've never been right
about anything.
Now, step aside, Toran,
and allow me to finish
this sorry business.
I will take over
from here.
Why? So you can take
the credit
and to make sure I remain
in disgrace?
I can't believe that
you were once considered clever.
Do you think that by completing
this one simple task
your reputation will be restored
at Central Command?
No, I suppose not.
Go back
to your sewing kit...
tailor.
Well, some people
should never be promoted.
Well, don't just stand there!
Your ship is waiting.
I'm going to see to it
that every Ferengi
on this station
shops in your store.
Ah, that alone
makes it all worthwhile.
You heard the man.
Get moving.
Thank you.
Both of you.
Yes, yes, yes.
Go, go, and quickly.
Keep up the good work.
Quark, I've got
to say good-bye.
Oh, just let them go.
It'll be less painful that way.
No, you don't understand.
I have to say good-bye to you.
I'm going with them.
But we had a deal.
I can't stay here.
Maybe one day I can come back
and we'll be together again
but not until my work is done.
So, all I have to do
to get you back
is wait until Cardassia becomes
a free and democratic society?
I promise...
I'll make it
worth the wait.
I don't suppose
I could come with you.
No, it's not your fight.
Besides, I could never
live with myself
if something happened to you.
I need to know that
you're here, safe.
That way, a part of me
will always be safe, too.
I love you, Quark.
I always will.
I love you, too.
I suggest we return
to the Promenade without delay.
You have to tell me.
Why did you do it?
Shoot Toran.
Well, why did you let
Professor Lang go?
I have no choice.
I love her.
And I love Cardassia,
which is why
I had to do what I did.
I don't understand.
That's the thing about love.
No one really
understands it, do they?