He only paid for one hour.
He's been in there for three
fighting the Battle
of Klachdachbrach
or some such thing,
over and over.
The Battle
of Klach D'kel Brakt
is a legendary Klingon victory
over the Romulans
almost a century ago.
Well, he's been
losing it all afternoon
and he says
he's not coming out
until he wins.
I banged on the door,
he sealed himself in.
I threatened
to shut off the power
he threatened to kill me.
Oh...
Since when did you add
ancient Klingon battles
to your holosuite programs?
The Captain
of the last Klingon ship
that went through the wormhole
sold some to me.
Ahh...
I know, I know.
It's brutal...
it's violent.
It's bloody.
But to the Klingons,
it's entertainment.
Shut off the power.
He'll kill you.
No, he said he'll kill you.
Shut it off.
Chay'pen Aha'bA?
Ar ghot k'Nel D'kulluH
marg raH gol low!
You dare interrupt the Battle
of Klach D'kel Brakt
you Ferengi k'pekt!
The battle is over.
The people are
waiting to celebrate
your victory.
They are?
Lead the way, then!
How did you get in here?
I am Koloth.
That doesn't answer
my question.
Yes, it does.
What are the charges
against him?
Charges?
No charges.
He's today's guest of honor.
You must be a very brave man
to attempt humor
at the expense
of a Klingon Dahar Master.
I apologize.
No offense intended.
Kor!
Sir...
if you'll wake up
I'll release you
into your friend's custody.
Oh.
Oh, Koloth.
Wlj jup...
my old friend.
Oh, I knew you'd be here.
You disgrace yourself
and our purpose.
I do not go into battle
with one whose honor is
washed away in brestanti ale.
Keep him!
Security reassignments, Major.
Sorry it took so long.
It's been a Klingon afternoon.
"A Klingon afternoon"?
Every time Klingons
visit the station
I wind up
with a Klingon afternoon.
But this is definitely one
I'll cherish forever.
There's a drunken Klingon
in my holding cell...
must be
a hundred years old...
singing battle songs.
Even his best friend...
who's probably
150 years old...
won't have anything
to do with him
so I get the pleasure
of listening to his repertoire.
Kor, Dahar Master
of the Klingons.
Did you say "Kor"?
That's what he announced,
right after winning
the Battle of Klach
D'kel Brakt at Quark's.
What is he doing here?
Did you get his friend's name?
Was it Kang?
No, it was...
- Koloth.
Come with me, Odo.
B'aski't Kor, B'askr'ip Kor
KoHman-a-tl, B'aski't Kor.
Hello, Kor.
I am thirsty.
Let him out.
Lieutenant...
I'll take responsibility.
I am very thirsty.
Kor, do you remember
Curzon Dax?
Curzon?
Oh, my dear friend Curzon?
I lift my ghoptu
to Curzon Dax, mm-hmm.
And I, who was Curzon Dax,
lift my ghoptu to you.
Oh.
Scorcher burn
on your 14th rib...
Huh?
And your left QiVon aches
every time your ship
hits warp eight.
Dax?!
My C-Curzon?
After 81 years, I...
I find you a kyamo-
looking woman.
Kiss me!
How about just
a great big hug?
Oh, Curzon,
my beloved old friend.
I'm Jadzia now.
Oh, well, Jadzia,
my beloved old friend.
Come on, Kor,
let's go find Koloth.
Koloth's here?
Look at him.
He practices cuts and thrusts
even with his food.
Little children do that.
A sharp knife is nothing
without a sharp eye.
Ooh.
Mmm, it's been 40 years
since even his good eye
was sharp.
Ah, it's luck
when you hit the plate.
I see that the Federation
insults us
by sending a Lieutenant
to greet us.
You never had much use
for the Federation
did you, Koloth?
I used to call you
D'akturak, "ice man,"
because no proposal...
no matter how reasonable,
no matter how much
it favored the
Klingon Empire...
would satisfy you.
You were the toughest man
I ever faced across
the negotiations table.
Do you not recognize
our old friend, Dax, hmm?
Dax?
Curzon's dead, but Dax
is alive as a part of me.
This is a mistake.
Kang must not have known.
Ah, but what
a beautiful mistake, hmm?
Is Kang coming?
Of course he's coming.
He's brought the four of us
back together after 81 years.
Could it possibly mean
that he's...
Yes.
That is exactly what it means.
I have found the Albino.
Ah.
Kang, do you remember
the first time we sat
together over bahgol?
It was the Korvat colony.
The Federation
and the Klingon Empire
were still enemies.
I never sat with you
before today.
I am Dax
godfather of your son.
You are no one's godfather.
I am Dax,
godfather of your son.
So, you are the same Dax
who took a blood oath with us
to seek vengeance?
Don't mistake a new face
for a new soul, Kang.
I still feel at one
with your family
just as I did
eight decades ago.
I hope one day, you'll embrace
me as a brother again.
Brother, ha!
Oh, brother, sister,
what's the difference?
We're all here now.
Speak to us, Kang.
Where is he?
Where did you find
the Albino?
Seven years ago... on Dayos IV
I met one of the Albino's
discarded wives.
I fed and clothed her.
I told her
the story of our sons.
She still feared him,
and told me nothing.
Three months ago, she died.
A week afterward, an amulet
she wore around her neck
was delivered to me
by messenger.
In it was the location
of the Albino's sanctuary.
Are you certain
that he's still there?
I have confirmed it
with traders who supply him.
It is on the fourth planet
of the Secarus system.
He has been hiding there
for nearly a quarter
of a century.
Hiding from us, no doubt.
I have been told he only has
40 men in his compound.
Evidently, he's become very lax
in his waning years.
The fool.
I wouldn't count
on information from traders.
The Albino might have
told them what to say
if anyone asks questions.
She's right.
The traders may
already have warned him
that we are coming.
They will never
warn anyone ever again.
This time, we will reach
the Albino
and when we do, I will cut
his heart out and eat it
while he watches me
with his dying breath.
I did not know, of course.
About Curzon?
I did not want to risk
contacting you by subspace.
I don't blame you.
That's how the Albino learned
we were coming to Galdonterre.
He has ears that reach
across the galaxy.
I don't know how.
Tell me about
my good friend, Curzon.
Did he die
an honorable death?
He died
in a hospital room
yelling at doctors
and friends
who were trying
to keep him alive
for one more miserable day.
Oh, that's a pity.
He was a good man.
He deserved to die in battle.
It pains me that I will never
see him again in this life.
Curzon was decorated many times
for his diplomatic achievements
but no honor touched him
as deeply as yours.
For a Klingon to choose
a Federation official
to be the godfather
of his son...
Curzon Dax opened
the door to peace.
He was the first Federation
diplomat I ever met
who truly seemed to understand
the Klingon nature.
Well, there was always a bit
of Klingon nature in Curzon.
His blood oath with you
was very important to him.
Would you eat from the heart
of the Albino, Jadzia Dax?
I know about the Trills
from my long friendship
with Curzon.
And I know that each new host
has no obligation
to past commitments.
And I know
that a Klingon blood oath
can never be broken.
The old Klingon ways
are passing.
There was a time
when I was a young man
the mere mention of the Klingon
Empire made worlds tremble.
Now our warriors are opening
restaurants and serving racht
to the grandchildren
of men I slaughtered in battle.
Things are not
what they used to be
not even the blood oath.
I know you, Kang.
You don't believe that.
What I believe
is no longer relevant.
You are released
from Curzon's oath.
You owe nothing to any of us.
Are you still reading
a plasma leak
in Lower Pylon One?
I can't seem to find it now.
It's been intermittent.
Let me do
a high-resolution scan.
Kira...
Uh-huh?
How many people did you kill?
What?
While you were
in the underground.
Too many.
Were they all...
faceless Cardassians
or did you know
who you were killing?
Why are we talking
about this?
If it bothers you,
we can stop.
It bothers me.
I'm sorry.
Why?
Were you thinking
about killing somebody?
Me?
Tell me.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Tell me.
80 years ago, there was
a band of depredators
led by an Albino
raiding Klingon colonies.
Three Klingon warships
were sent to stop him.
One of the Captains was
a close friend of Curzon's.
The mission was successful.
Most of them were captured,
but the Albino escaped.
In his last message
to the Klingons
he promised to take revenge
on the firstborn of each
of the three Captains.
A few years later,
he kept his word.
Somehow, he infected
three innocent children
with a genetic virus
that killed them.
One of them was my godson.
I'm sorry.
But, Jadzia...
that was Curzon's godson.
I took a blood oath
to avenge his death.
Curzon took a blood oath.
I can still remember
the boy's funeral.
He was named Dax, for me.
You've found this Albino?
We know where he is.
The three Klingons
came here to tell me...
Look, you've said yourself
every new life for a Trill
has to be a new life.
If not, you'd wind up
paying off old debts forever.
These Klingons can't
possibly expect you
to keep this oath.
No, they don't.
That's just it.
They say I have
no obligation to them.
But I do.
I know it, I feel it.
If not to them,
I owe it to Curzon.
Jadzia...
your questions about my...
experience with killing...
if you're wondering
what it's like...
When you take someone's life
you lose a part
of your own, as well.
I need another arm.
Or am I doomed to choose
between perfection
and the palate?
Let me spare you
that decision.
Mmm! Mmm... mmm.
Ah...
majQa'.
To the rescue.
Dax, may I present
these two... students
of... Klingon history.
Would you excuse us
for a minute?
Hmm?
Ooh, well, only a minute,
my students.
Well, you certainly don't
share Curzon's priorities.
About going after the Albino,
I do.
Kang and Koloth
don't want me
to come with you.
Well, Kang thinks too much.
Koloth doesn't feel enough.
And where do you stand?
Huh? Hmm?
Oh, of course
you should come.
The splendor of fighting
and killing
a bloodbath in the cause
of vengeance...
who wouldn't want to come?
Would you speak
to them for me?
It means far more to me
than I realized.
Hmm, Koloth spends
all his time
practicing in the holosuite.
He listens to no one.
And if Kang's made up his mind,
there's nothing I can do.
And you call yourself
a history teacher?
What of your own history?
You are Kor, Dahar Master.
They cheered you
at Klach D'kel Brakt.
Your voice weighed heavily on
the course of Klingon events.
You shame me.
No, please don't feel that.
Huh! The only weight
I carry now, dear comrade
is... is my own bulbous body.
I... I was once,
if you remember
far less than you see...
and far more
than I have become.
I'm sorry.
My memories are still
of Kor, a great warrior.
Quark, you...
devious little Ha'DIBah!
Bring wine.
Nice of you to stop.
I'm coming with you.
Curzon Dax was a politician.
It was a diplomatic ploy
for him to bond himself
to us in a blood oath.
That's a lie.
Are... you?
I am practicing here.
Leave while you can.
When you agree that I can
fulfill my part of the oath.
Your presence will jeopardize
the rest of us.
Leave me.
Computer, I want
a Klingon bat'leth.
Tip to tip
116 centimeters
weight 5.3 kilos
with an exterior hand-gripping
diameter of five centimeters.
Blades composite baakonite.
Ah, a warrior's configuration.
Now what are you going
to do with it?
I'm going to fight you.
And if my hand should slip,
and you should die?
Your hand would never slip
unless you've become
old and feeble.
Come on, Koloth,
surely you can take me down.
There is tension
on your face, Koloth.
You ought to drink more.
Stand up.
Your presence
against the Albino
will do honor to our cause.
Well, that's a surprise
from the great stone face.
Releasing you
from Curzon's oath
is not enough.
I can see that now.
It is agreed then.
No!
I tell you now, you will
not be part of the quest.
Why do you dismiss her
like some useless
t'ooho'mlrah?
We cannot go
to an enemy stronghold
with your sickly chest
announcing us.
There is nothing...
nothing wrong with my chest.
Nothing that won't
get us all killed
before we reach battle.
Come.
Ah, I need no nurse's hand.
You can't deny my right
for vengeance.
You try to speak
like a Klingon
but the words do not
fit in your mouth.
You said that to me before,
Kang, do you remember?
I do not wish to discuss it
any further.
The Korvat colony.
First day of negotiations,
I walked out on you
right in the middle of that
longwinded speech of yours.
You should have seen
the look on your face.
Nobody had ever
had the kajanpak't
to show their back
to the great Kang
before Curzon did.
I almost killed Curzon
that day.
I knew I had to get you
very, very angry
or my mission wouldn't succeed.
Getting you angry with me
was the only way
to begin to create a bond
between us.
Curzon understood Klingons.
And he also understood
what he was doing
when he took
a Klingon blood oath.
You can't expect me
to stay here
and not avenge
my own godson's murder.
You can't ask me to live
with that kind of dishonor.
I cannot dishonor myself
by allowing you to die
in Curzon's place.
Who's talking about dying?
I have no intention of dying.
You dishonor yourself
already, Kang
by placing your honor
above mine.
No Klingon warrior would
leave a comrade behind
while he goes off to battle.
Perhaps you're right.
Klingon honor isn't
what it used to be.
Are you trying
to anger me again?
You think the same trick
would work twice?
I understand Klingons.
All right then, it worked.
Come and fight with us.
Come and be damned.
Come in.
I was just about
to come see you.
No.
No what?
No leave of absence.
Kira shouldn't have told you.
Kira is my First Officer.
I don't have to tell you
what this oath meant to Curzon.
Jadzia Dax took an oath, too,
when she joined Starfleet.
You're subject to
orders, Lieutenant.
Don't do it, Benjamin.
Don't make me disobey
a direct order.
I never understood this.
I mean, whatever
else Curzon was
he did have
a fundamental morality.
He wouldn't condone murder
any more than I would.
And yet he swore
to kill this Albino
and now you plan to go out
and kill in his name.
What about the laws
of the Federation?
The Klingons have
their own set of laws.
This is justice to them.
And to you?
I've chosen to respect
their codes of honor
in this matter, yes.
You really think
you're capable of doing this?
I don't know.
There's only one way
to find out, isn't there?
Let's say you are.
Let's say you even
survive this insanity.
You expect to come back here
and resume your duties,
as though nothing's happened?
I guess that'll be up to you.
The compound is made
of riddinite.
There are several walls
that separate
the main house
from the rest of the grounds.
The main power source is here.
There is an armory there.
Any information about
the positioning
of the sentries?
They are posted
at standing intervals
75 meters apart
along the perimeter.
Standing, no patrols?
That's what I'm told.
Perhaps he thinks
we're already dead
and have stopped chasing him.
Or perhaps he's made
his defenses look weak
for our benefit.
Hmm, she may be right.
We have to assume
the guards patrol the perimeter.
At 75 meters apart, they're out
of eye contact with each other.
He wouldn't be that stupid.
We must expect them to be
no farther than...
50 meters apart.
Fine, it makes no difference.
Doesn't it?
If we assume he has
adequate defenses...
a minimum of 50 guards...
then we should use
a N'yengoren strategy.
No!
I will not sneak
into his bedroom
and murder him
like a kah'plakt.
I want him to see us coming.
I say we make a direct attack
boldly through the threshold.
The guards will be too scattered
to defend against us.
We will overwhelm them
to glorious victory!
Or a glorious death.
It is a good day to die.
Come on, old comrade.
For the last time,
let's sharpen our blades.
So, we talk about dying again.
A Klingon warrior is
always prepared to die.
Yes, but to invite death
with a direct assault
against a superior force...
Kang, what are you doing?
What's really going on here?
Loyalty blinds
Kor and Koloth, but not me.
This is not a plan for battle.
It's a plan for suicide.
If it were someone else
I might think you were paid
to lure us here.
How can you say that?
I took a blood oath with you.
That's why you didn't
want me to come...
because you knew
you were coming to die.
When the amulet arrived
with the location of the Albino
I went to the Secarus system,
to see if it was true.
Somehow, the instant I arrived,
the Albino knew I was there.
He contacted me.
He sent an invitation...
to one last glorious battle.
He said he was tired
of this lifelong pursuit.
He swore to send 40 of his
strongest, most skilled men
against us in honorable battle.
And I agreed.
But why?
Because...
this is our last chance.
If we cannot reach the Albino
we can at least die
an honorable death
trying to reach him.
A death a Klingon
Dahar Master deserves.
You know what, Kang?
I think you Klingons
embrace death too easily.
You treat death like a lover.
I think living is
a lot more attractive.
I think an honorable victory
is better
than an honorable defeat.
I know the Albino's defenses.
There is no chance
of victory here.
What if they had no phasers?
That might make the odds
a little better
don't you think?
How do you intend
to disarm them all?
When we establish a low orbit,
we modulate your disrupter banks
to bombard the compound
with tetryon particles.
Every directed energy weapon
would be neutralized.
You're certain
such a thing could be done?
Well, if Curzon were here,
you'd be out of luck
but Jadzia Dax is
a science officer.
We would also be unable
to use our disrupters
but who among them could match
our skills with a bat'leth?
Not many.
We're about 40 minutes
from the Secarus system.
I think we should cloak
and then you and I, old friend,
should sharpen our blades, too.
Perhaps...
it is a good day to live.
You say they promised you
an honorable battle...
hand-to-hand combat
at the main threshold.
That's right.
Take a look at this.
This indicates a gravitic mine
buried at the main threshold.
Yes, and he plans to detonate it
the moment we enter
the compound.
That's what you get for making
a deal with the devil, Kang.
On the other hand,
this gives us
an advantage we
wouldn't otherwise have.
He's expecting us
at the front door.
How do we know
that he's even inside?
Good question.
Wait here.
Where are you going?
I'm going to find out
if he's inside.
And how do you intend
to do that?
I'll ask somebody.
We would be wise
to shut down his sensor array
before we attack.
It's controlled
from this power station.
Yes, but a power failure
would signal our presence.
At the same time
that you shut down the sensors
I'll create a diversion
at the armory
to misdirect their response.
Good strategy
but whoever creates
a diversion
will have to run across
this field to escape.
With all due respect
none of you are as
quick as you once were.
I'll volunteer for that job.
Agreed.
It seems this is
the best place for entry.
Right here.
I encountered
a helpful lookout.
The Albino is inside.
His overconfidence will
be the death of him.
Well, he's in there now,
but the moment we attack
he will move to a secured
command post here.
It will be midday
in about an hour.
Can you create the diversion
in the armory by then?
I think so.
We will be in position
at the powerhouse.
May Kahless guide us
on this day of vengeance.
Excuse me?
Could you tell me where
the tennis courts are?
I seem to be lost.
Huh?
There she is, over there.
I'm not firing.
What's wrong?
I have no power.
Reset, reset!
Report.
The armory's been sabotaged.
I've diverted the forward
patrols to that area.
Cancel those orders.
Move all guards
to the inner defense line.
Make sure
the power station is secure.
Go.
Yes, sir.
None of the phasers
are functioning.
Not functioning?
We're running
diagnostics now.
Use long-range sensors
to check
for interference
from a cloaked ship in orbit.
In the meantime, have the guards
fix kuttars to their rifles
and prepare
for hand-to-hand combat.
I can't make contact
with the power station.
They must have already broken
through the inner defense line.
Move the perimeter guards
into the house.
Sir, without power,
we have no communications.
Then get out there
and tell them yourself!
I don't want that Klingon
filth to get in this...
Look upon your executioners
killer of children.
Get them!
Koloth!
I didn't see him coming.
Even you cannot have eyes
in the back of your head,
my friend.
Quiet now... rest.
I still have work to do.
I will not die before you
do, you thunderous bulk.
The story of your courage
will never die.
I will sing the story.
The children of all Klingons
will know of this day.
You'll die far quicker
than your son did, Kang.
No vengeance today, Kang.
And who are you, girl?
You knew me as Curzon Dax.
The Trill, of course.
You're far too young and lovely
to sport such a deadly weapon.
All right then...
use it, if that's
what you came to do.
Kill me in cold blood.
Run me through the belly
and cut out my heart.
Isn't that what your
blood oath promised?
Or have you lost your
appetite, my dear?
Thank you for saving
the death blow for me.
You have honored me
one last time...
godfather to my son.
Where is Koloth?
He's dead.
Oh...
I was right, Dax.
It is a good day to die.
It's never a good day
to lose a friend.
Ki-naH-naH, lo-maytoo
Ki-naH-naH, lo-maytaH...