The Cardassian Freighter Bok'Nor
is requesting permission
to depart Upper Pylon 1
in three minutes.
We have an incoming
Bolian vessel
at coordinates 101 mark 38.
Give the Bok'Nor
a clear trajectory
out of the traffic pattern.
Acknowledged.
Feel like getting together
for dinner tonight?
Can't. I'm having dinner
with Captain Boday.
The Gallamite?
You're going
out on a date with him?
Is something wrong with that?
No... not at all.
He happens to be brilliant.
His brain is twice the size
of yours and mine.
I know, I've seen it.
It's not his fault Gallamites
have transparent skulls.
No, it's not.
It's... not exactly the view
I want to have with dinner.
You know, Kira,
sometimes I think you place
too much emphasis
on how men look.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
Look, when I kiss a man
good night
I like to know
where I'm kissing him.
I guess seven lifetimes gives me
a somewhat broader perspective.
Well, since I just have
one lifetime
I have to be
a little more particular
about whom I go out with.
I never said
I wasn't particular.
I'm not the one
who dates Ferengis.
And what's that
supposed to mean?
Nothing.
Releasing docking clamps
at Upper Pylon 1.
That's funny.
I'm picking up elevated...
DS9 to Bok'Nor.
Shut down your engines.
Repeat.
Shut down your engines!
Report.
Some kind of impulse overload.
Checking.
Ops to all
engineering personnel.
Report to rescue stations.
We have an S.I.D. In progress.
There's nothing left of it.
There's no one left to rescue.
Kelindide, rodinium...
nothing unusual there.
All materials commonly used
in Cardassian ship construction.
Maybe it was a malfunction
in the impulse generator.
I'd like to be able
to tell you that, Major
but it's too soon to be sure.
I can't believe the Cardassians
have waited this long
for an official explanation.
Anything, Chief?
No sign of an explosive device
yet, sir.
I've got every Admiral within
subspace range on my back.
Can I at least tell them
that it looks like an accident?
Well, I wouldn't do that yet.
When?
I'll let you know, sir.
Anything from the Cardassians,
Commander?
Not a word.
All Bajoran outposts
have been put on alert
for retaliatory strikes.
The provisional government
has made a statement
disavowing any responsibility.
Maybe it really was an accident.
I mean, it is a possibility.
An accident involving
a Cardassian ship
in Bajoran space?
If I were a Cardassian,
I wouldn't easily accept...
That's odd.
What?
I'm picking up traces
of a mercassium compound.
Mercassium?
There shouldn't have been
any mercassium
on board that ship.
Well, there was.
Meaning?
I'm not quite sure yet.
Well, is mercassium
some kind of explosive?
No, it's a synthetic composite
used in shield generator
construction
by the Federation.
We don't share that technology
with anyone.
Chief, I don't think you're
going to find any evidence
of an explosive device.
Lieutenant, respectfully
these kinds of things
take time, and I...
I don't think
you're going to find
any evidence
of an explosive device
because I'm pretty sure
it was an implosive
protomatter device
designed to match
the impulse signature.
Just before the explosion
I picked up a sudden increase
in their fusion rate.
I've been trying to find
any sign of malfunction
in the Bok'Nor's
engines to explain it
but there just isn't one.
This doesn't look
like an accident.
The fusion shock
had to be caused
by something external
to the impulse drive system.
If a protomatter device
was attached to the cross-feeds
that could have created
the overload
and we'd never see
any sign of it.
Can you prove
that's what happened?
Maybe
if we can get
a high resolution spectra
of the impulse debris
but that's going to take...
Time.
Yes, I know.
Get it started.
I'll tell the Admirals.
Sisko out.
Benjamin.
Ah.
Cal, thanks for coming
on such short notice.
I wish it didn't take
a disaster like this
to bring us back together again.
Hi, Calvin.
Jadzia Dax.
Dax?!
My goodness!
Well, you look a lot better
than when last I saw you.
Chief of Security Odo.
Commander Calvin Hudson
Starfleet's attaché to
the Federation colonies
in the new
Demilitarized Zone.
You must be concerned about
the colonies' security
at a time like this.
Well, we haven't noticed
any unusual deployment
from the Cardassians
along the border.
Neither have we, and that's
what's got me worried.
Let's go into my office.
Lieutenant, I don't
have time this trip
but you and I have a few stories
to catch up on.
- Next time.
That woman knows more about me
than any woman ever has.
More than my wife, even.
Tell me about it.
Don't you find things
a little uncomfortable?
Oh, no, she's a good officer.
Yes, but Curzon was...
She's not Curzon.
Now, you two aren't, I mean...
Oh, no.
She may not be Curzon
but she is Dax.
Yes, that would be
extremely... strange.
So, Ben, how is Jake?
As tall as me.
No!
He throws inside to knock
the old man off the plate.
A little chin music, huh?
Yeah, he's growing up
too fast.
Yeah.
It must have been difficult
for you.
At least I didn't have
a child to raise by myself.
Well, we kind of helped
each other through it.
I heard about Gretchen.
I wanted to be there for you.
There was just
no way to get back.
I know that, Ben.
You know, I was hoping
when they sent me
to the colonies
that you and I would
have a little time
for some R&R together.
Who's got R&R time?
I know.
You can't imagine
how my life has changed
since the Federation
abandoned these colonies.
Abandoned them?
Doesn't your presence?
My presence there is a joke.
I am supposed to help
these colonies function
under the terms
of the new treaty.
Now, Ben, what the hell
does that mean?
I thought these colonists
wanted to stay.
That they refused to evacuate.
The treaty gave away
their territory
to the Cardassians...
territory that these people
had invested their lives in.
Now, Ben, if you knew them
as I do
you'd know why they can't leave.
It's a bad treaty.
The Federation
gave away too much.
Several Cardassian colonies
wanted to stay on the Federation
side of the zone, too.
It seemed like
a reasonable compromise.
Oh, yes,
the Cardassians would love
to have their colonies
in our territory
because they know
we'd protect them
but they have no intention
of doing the same for ours.
A number of Admirals
at Starfleet Command are worried
the destruction of the Bok'Nor
might jeopardize the treaty.
Oh, are they really?
As the two ranking officers
along the Cardassian border
we've been asked to assess
the potential risk.
There is no risk, Ben.
None.
I have been dealing
with the Cardassians
most of my professional life,
and believe me
they are very pleased with
what they got from the treaty.
They are not about
to risk losing
all they've gained
by sending forces into the zone.
They're much too slick for that.
If I were you, I'd be
very concerned with security
along the Bajoran border.
Are you surprised they haven't
responded at all yet?
Well, Ben, you and I both know
they never let you see
what you expect to see.
They'll respond.
Quarters have been arranged
through discreet channels...
Deck 7, Section 4-G.
I suggest you keep a low profile
until your ship arrives.
Can I get you something?
You are Quark, aren't you?
I assure you,
the warrant is out of date.
I cleared that matter up
months ago.
Warrant?
Oh, uh, when you recognized me,
I assumed...
You are counting your receipts.
It is logical to conclude
you are the proprietor
of the establishment.
You're very observant.
What can I do for you?
I was hoping to discuss
a business proposition.
With me?
Uh, perhaps I should explain
about that slip of the tongue.
Your past
is of no consequence to me.
I'm delighted
to hear you say that
because nothing
would please me more
than to make a fresh start
with the Vulcans, Ms., uh?
- Sakonna.
Such a handsome name
for such a handsome young woman.
What will you have to drink?
Wait a minute.
I have just the thing.
Vulcan port.
Three centuries old.
Very rare, very expensive.
Shall I pour you a glass?
No.
Not even a taste?
It's exquisite.
I'm not thirsty
thus, I see no reason
to have a drink.
Well, it'll be right here
should you develop a thirst.
Now, uh, you mentioned
a business proposition.
It is a private matter.
I would rather not
discuss it here.
Then we can discuss
it over dinner.
That is, we can plan
the business meeting
to coincide with when you think
you might get hungry.
That would be acceptable.
That would be wonderful.
How does 8:00
sound to your tummy?
I will return then.
And, by the way
I'd love to melt
that cold Vulcan heart of yours.
Bleech.
Oh!
Oh, here, allow me.
Thank you.
Ah! Oh...
Jake-o?
Your son is not here,
Commander.
Dukat.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to startle you.
Where is he?
Who? Your son?
How would I know?
I just...
Commander, you don't?
Do you think I would ever
do anything to harm your son?
I think
you're capable of anything.
You wound me, sir.
I'm here as your friend.
Sisko to Kira.
Please do not do anything
hastily, Commander.
We must talk in private.
Yes, Commander?
Major, I want you to find Jake.
Is he missing?
I don't know.
Find out where he is
and let me know.
Understood.
How the hell
did you get in here?
I was an unregistered passenger
on a Kotakian ship
that docked here this morning.
I slipped in
through the cargo bay.
Hmm. And made your way here
without anyone seeing you.
I was the Commander
of this station
for almost ten years.
When one knows
the various corridors
and passageways as well as I...
Oh, by the way, I love
what you've done
with these quarters.
Kira to Sisko.
Jake's fine, Commander.
He's with Nog,
watching the women
coming off the Bajoran transport
at Docking Bay 1.
Shall I have him
brought to your quarters?
No, that's all right.
Thank you, Major.
Sisko out.
There. You see?
Safe and sound.
What are you doing here?
You have a problem.
Do I?
The Bok'Nor?
Is this the Cardassian
Central Command's way
of responding to my communiqués?
On the contrary.
Central Command
has no idea I'm here.
It's true.
I'm here unofficially
to help you find out
the truth about the Bok'Nor.
Why would you want to help me?
Because I already know
the truth.
Do you know who's responsible?
- I do.
- Who?
You are.
Well, not you personally,
Commander.
I know you to be
an honorable man.
You're not one to sneak around
attaching implosion devices
to impulse engines.
But believe it or not
there are those of your brethren
who are willing
to do such things.
Morally superior human beings
and other members
of the Federation.
I'm supposed
to take your word for that?
Of course not.
It's my job to convince you
so you can clean up
your own house
instead of forcing us
to do it for you
which would certainly
endanger the new treaty.
We'll need
one of your runabouts.
Where are we going?
The Volon colonies.
The Demilitarized Zone?
Hmm. Not so demilitarized,
I'm afraid.
I can't help but notice
that my controls
are not illuminated.
Isn't it customary
for both seats
to be turned on, so that
I may pilot the craft
in the event of an emergency?
If there's an emergency,
I guess you're out of luck.
Commander, I'm not
going to sit here
and steal
your little technical secrets
I promise you.
I appreciate your assurances
but Cardassians are famous
for their photographic memories.
Oh, so you turn off my controls
so I don't have enough light
to take my photograph,
is that it?
I've heard they put
Cardassian children
in intense
mind training programs
when they're four years old.
Is that true?
The Cardassian
educational system
is unparalleled
in the quadrant.
If you don't mind taking
the joy out of growing up.
Education is power.
Joy is vulnerability.
What?
Your reaction
surprises me, Commander.
I thought you
would understand.
Of all the humans I've met
you strike me
as the most joyless
and the least vulnerable.
I am when I'm with you.
Well said.
But, in truth,
I'm looking forward
to getting to know you
better on this journey.
I think we know each other
well enough.
Is that a ramscoop control
or a deflector grid panel?
Just curious.
It really doesn't matter.
Cardassian pursuit vessels
are years ahead of this design.
What is it?
Long-range sensors
are picking up
a distress signal.
From who?
A Federation merchant vessel
under attack
by Cardassians.
I'm reading
two Cardassian attack vessels
just inside
the Demilitarized Zone.
That's not possible.
I promise you, Commander,
we would not violate the treaty.
The merchant vessel's
com links are down.
I can't raise them.
Computer, fix source coordinates
of the distress signal
and lay in a new course...
warp 3.
I hope you don't mind.
Not at all.
I'm as curious about this
as you are.
What type of Cardassian
ships are they?
Patrol cruisers?
No, much smaller.
They look like shuttlecraft.
Cardassian shuttles
attacking a Federation
merchant ship?
They seem to be armed
with Galor-class phaser banks.
They must be from
Cardassian colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Hail them.
- No response.
- Open a channel.
Go ahead.
To the pilots of the Cardassian
attack vessels.
This is Gul Dukat,
Commander of the Second Order.
Please respond.
This is Gul Dukat, security
identification: A-D-L 4-Zero.
I order you to immediately
disengage your attack.
We're still two minutes away.
The Federation vessel's shields
are down to 40 percent.
Hail those
Cardassians again.
I don't know who you are
or where you come from
but you're going to pay
for this, I promise you.
Answer me immediately,
or I personally will fire
the photons
that will destroy you.
Arm the photons.
The photon launcher is...
I know.
I knew all about these controls
before I ever came on board.
Tell me when we're
in torpedo range.
Stand by.
I'm picking up another ship
moving toward them.
That's a Federation signature,
I believe, Commander.
It sure isn't from Starfleet.
I've never seen a ship
configuration like that before.
It almost seems
like someone has modified
an old support courier.
Hmm.
Hailing them.
No response.
They fired torpedoes.
What kind of civilian
vessel that size
would be carrying photon?
Something from one
of your colonies, perhaps?
Now do you begin to see,
Commander
that without any help
from either one of us
they've managed to start
their own little war out here?
I hope you're hungry.
I've planned
a wonderful meal for us
starting with plomeek soup
which I know is
a traditional Vulcan favorite
followed by jumbo
Romulan mollusks.
You can't get those back
on Vulcan anymore, can you?
Do you eat in this grand
a manner every night?
Certainly not; this
is a special occasion.
It is?
The commencement
of a new business relationship
is the most special
occasion for any Ferengi.
It's a cause for opening
great bottles of wine
dancing into the wee,
small hours of the morning.
We'll let it breathe
for a few minutes.
Very well;
I will attempt to respect
some of your cultural
idiosyncrasies.
I will drink the wine,
but I won't dance.
Maybe you'll change your mind
after you drink the wine.
No, I won't.
Oh, come on.
Somewhere inside that cool,
controlled exterior of yours
there is a wild woman
screaming to get out.
Maybe by the end of the night
you'll be dancing
on the table tops.
Maybe not.
Is it appropriate to begin
our business discussion now?
Rule of Acquisition
Number 214:
Never begin
a business negotiation
on an empty stomach.
Rule of Acquisition?
Yes.
Every Ferengi
business transaction
is governed
by 285 Rules of Acquisition
to ensure a fair and honest deal
for all parties concerned.
Well, most of them, anyway.
Commendable... to create
a code of behavior
for business transactions...
Is logical.
And quite reassuring.
Do Vulcans have
anything similar?
In structure, it reminds one
of the Vulcan Bill of Rights
which guarantees the fundamental
personal freedoms
of every Vulcan citizen.
Same thing exactly.
May I propose a toast?
Is this another
cultural idiosyncrasy?
Yes. You know, I can't describe
the honor I feel at this moment.
It's rare that a Ferengi
and a Vulcan
can overcome
their inherent differences
to see eye-to-eye
as we are doing.
I've always had
the greatest respect
for Vulcans, even though
the few I've met
haven't exactly felt
the same way about me.
You're a noble people...
and I salute you.
Now then, what kind
of business proposition
do you have in mind?
I wish to procure weapons.
I beg your pardon?
Guns, phaser banks,
photon torpedoes...
- Shh.
...troop transports
and a number
of cobalt-thorium devices.
My list is quite extensive.
You're a gun runner?
I am prepared
to pay in latinum
and I will very likely need
a continuous supply
for the foreseeable future.
You're not like other Vulcans,
are you?
The Federation merchant ship
refused to be boarded!
So your ships
just decided to open fire?
It was clear the Federation ship
was carrying weapons
through the Demilitarized Zone.
That ship was carrying
medical supplies to Saltok IV.
Ben, what are you doing here?
I'm not sure yet.
Gul Dukat asked me
to accompany him.
Dukat...
no one informed us
you were coming.
I decided an impromptu visit
would be preferable
so you wouldn't be bothered
with special preparations.
I see.
Commander Sisko, you know
my counterpart
from the colonies, Gul Evek.
I'm glad you're here
to listen to this, Commander.
We monitored the attack
on the way in.
Yes, "monitor"
is the proper word
because none of the ships
would respond to our hails.
Even the Cardassian pilots
refused to acknowledge me.
A strange voice
from a Federation runabout.
I gave them
my security identification.
Well, obviously,
they had their hands full.
With an unprovoked attack.
Unprovoked, was it?
Do you deny that
the Federation is engaging
in organized
terrorist activities
against the Cardassian people
deliberately undermining
this treaty?
The Federation does not conduct
secret wars.
Then perhaps you can explain
where the Federation ship
came from...
the one outfitted
with photon torpedoes.
Explain why your ships
were armed
with Galor-class phaser banks.
They have a right
to defend themselves
against organized
terrorist activities.
I haven't heard any proof yet
of organized
terrorist activities.
Because there is none.
On the contrary.
We have the confession
of the Federation terrorist
responsible for the destruction
of the Bok'Nor
at your station, Commander.
Confession?
A 43-year-old male human,
William Patrick Samuels
born Bergen, Norway, Earth...
We know who he is.
What have you done with him?
Came to the Federation colony
on Volon II 20 years ago.
Married, wife's name Louise,
two female children
aged 14 and 12.
He was quite cooperative
once we apprehended
him on Deep Space 9.
Begin.
My name is William Samuels.
I am being held for crimes
against the Cardassian people.
I have been well-treated.
I have confessed
that as a member of a well-armed
anti-Cardassian force
organized
by Federation colonists
I set an implosion device
that destroyed
the freighter Bok'Nor.
I deeply regret participating
in this arbitrary attack
that led to the deaths
of over 75 crewmen.
To my wife and children...
I'm sorry
and... I love you.
He would have
confessed to anything
after you were through with him.
On the contrary.
He confessed quite early
in the interrogation
procedure...
far sooner than we expected.
I believe he truly felt remorse.
We want to talk
to him ourselves.
Bring him in.
Unfortunately, he committed
suicide in his cell.
Come on, come on!
It's all right!
Dukat, get them out of here!
Go on, we'll talk later.
We can't let them
get away with this.
We'll talk later.
You go on!
Get him out of here.
I knew him.
Bill Samuels was a farmer.
He cultivated his land
for 20 years.
He raised two children
on that land.
He made something
out of that land
and the Federation told him
he had to give it all
up to the Cardassians.
Well, he just was not
willing to do that.
And it was people like him
who made both sides realize
that some accommodation had
to be made for the colonies
so they could stay.
The Cardassians
have no intention
of allowing these
people to stay.
They will either force them out
or they will kill them.
It's already started.
Not a day goes by
when there's not some
random act of violence
against our people.
Every Federation colonist knows
you do not go out alone
at night.
Can you imagine living
under that kind of fear?
If you're saying
the Cardassian authorities
are not enforcing the laws...
Enforcing the laws?
The Cardassian authorities
were part of a mob that
stoned two colonists
on the streets of Ropal City
three days ago.
That's something the Federation
can take up with the Cardassians
at the highest levels.
Well, that will help a lot.
The word is
the Cardassian High Command
is arming their colonists
to the teeth.
You really think they'd risk
sending weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone
and breaking the treaty?
I think they'll find
a way to do it
that's not so obvious.
Not long ago, we caught
the Cardassians shipping weapons
to Bajoran extremists through
a third party, the Yridians.
That sounds about right.
Would the Bok'Nor have been
transferring weapons
to someone else
to bring in here?
If it was,
then the transfer was made
before the ship
reached the station.
The cargo holds
of the Bok'Nor were empty.
Do you think he did it?
Samuels?
I don't know.
They could have forced him
to make a false confession
and then killed him.
I don't think Gul Dukat
would drag me all the way here
unless he knew
he could prove it.
Well, maybe he did do it, Ben.
I don't know.
Damn!
I've got to go see his wife.
I don't know
what I'm going to tell her.
It makes you pine for
the good old, dull days
in New Berlin, doesn't it?
Sausage and beer all around
and everyone's idea
of a good time
was the mazurka festival.
Gretchen and Jennifer had a ball
there together, didn't they?
I'll never forget the sight
of you in those lederhosen.
I still have the hat.
Is there something larger
going on here, Cal?
Are these colonists organizing
some kind of terrorist campaign?
Well, if they are
they're not about
to tell me about it.
But I'll tell you one thing,
Ben.
Between you and me
those people have every right
to defend themselves.
When the Federation
said good-bye to them
they left them no other choice.
You're very quiet, Commander.
You knew about Samuels
before we left.
I knew about his confession,
yes.
I didn't know he was...
I was as surprised
as you were by his death.
No one is going to buy
your suicide story.
I don't care what he did.
This kind of barbaric disregard
for life
will gut this treaty.
If it means anything,
I entirely agree.
I told Evek he was a fool
to let Samuels die.
A good interrogator doesn't
allow his subject to die.
You lose the advantage.
That's all
you're interested in, isn't it?
The advantage.
Oh, now, don't go spouting off
your holier-than-thou
Federation fair play dogma.
And lest we forget,
your man was responsible
for the deaths
of 78 innocent crewmen.
What was the Bok'Nor
transporting?
The Bok'Nor had just delivered
14 metric tons of golside ore
to the Regulon system
prior to its arrival
at the wormhole.
You're sure
it wasn't carrying weapons?
Weapons? To whom?
To the Cardassians
in the Demilitarized Zone.
No, the route of the Bok'Nor
didn't take it anywhere near
the Demilitarized Zone.
It could have rendezvoused
with someone else...
with the Lissepians, maybe.
They could have transferred
the weapons to them
and they could have taken
the weapons to...
Commander!
I know you'd love to find
some justification
for this mass murder
to ease
your Federation conscience
but if the Bok'Nor was carrying
weapons, I would know.
And on the lives of my children,
I swear to you it was not.
I didn't know you had children.
Seven.
I received your message.
How soon will it be available?
My source can have
everything ready tomorrow.
Say by 1400 hours.
That's not soon enough.
I must leave
the station tonight.
You're leaving so soon?
My plans have changed.
Can your source have the
materials ready by tonight?
I guess he'll have to.
I have your latinum,
if you'd like to count it.
Are you trustworthy?
I'm a Vulcan.
Of course.
Just a little joke.
I'm sure it's all there.
Well, it wouldn't hurt
to give it a quick
count, I suppose.
I will have it brought
to your quarters.
I was looking forward
to showing you more ways
to mix business with pleasure.
Perhaps in the future.
I do find you...
intriguing, Quark.
"Intriguing."
You can stay in the guest suite
on Level H-2
while you arrange transport
back to Cardassia.
I'll have a security guard
meet you there.
Starfleet security,
if you don't mind, Commander.
Some of the Bajoran deputies
are still around
from the good old days
when I was in charge.
I understand.
If there's anything else
I can do
to assist you in
your investigation...
I think I can
handle it from here.
Chief?
Yes, sir.
I've got answers for you
but I'm not sure
you're going to like them.
It was an implosive device.
Yes, sir.
And not only that...
Not only that, it was
a Federation implosive device.
Yes, sir. The traces
of mercassium we found
were from the casing
of the device itself.
It had to be
a Federation design.
Get me Starfleet Command
on subspace.
Commander, is there anything
you'd like me to communicate
to the provisional
government?
Tell them some reckless colonist
in the Demilitarized Zone
blew up the Bok'Nor.
There's no further threat
of Cardassian reprisals
to Bajor.
I'll advise all of our outposts
to stand down.
Sir, are... are we facing
the prospect of war here?
Not if I can help it.
But that's what
the colonists are after.
I don't think they know
what they're after, Major.
I just know
they have to be stopped
and it's Starfleet's job
to stop them.
Sir, I know this is
none of my business...
But you're going to give
me your opinion anyway.
I don't know
what the Cardassians told you.
They played a confession
of the man who planted the bomb.
A man they most likely
tortured to death.
And you don't think you might
be playing into their hands?
I've got people out there
killing people, Major.
You suggest I turn
a blind eye to that?
They don't have a right
to defend themselves?
They've crossed the line!
If Starfleet is unwilling
to defend their people...
They chose to live
with the Cardassians!
Well, I didn't!
But I lived with them
for 26 years
before the liberation came.
Every Bajoran lived with them
in constant fear.
I know what those colonists
are going through.
Most of all, I know
that the Cardassians
can't be trusted
to keep their side
of the bargain in this treaty.
So, you'd suggest the Federation
not keep our side
of the bargain either...
perhaps by arming
these colonists?
I can tell you
one thing for certain.
The Cardassians are the enemy,
not your own colonists
and if Starfleet
can't understand that
then the Federation
is even more naive
than I already think it is.
I've been sent to relieve you.
There must be some mistake.
I just reported for duty
an hour...
Yes?
Sorry to disturb you, sir
but there's a message here
from Commander Sisko.
We have been asked to escort you
to Airlock 11, sir.
A Cardassian freighter
has just arrived.
Is there a problem?
Apparently, another bomb
has been found and disarmed.
Where's Commander Sisko?
Comfortably asleep
in his quarters, I hope.
Remember me?
I take it
we're not about to board
a Cardassian freighter.
What do you think
they're telling him?
With two kidnappings
and a ship exploding
in the course of a week
I'm sure they've got
a few things to say.
It's their own fault.
I've been warning them
since the beginning.
What are you talking about...
their fault?
You're in charge of security.
If you will let me be
in charge of security
I will give you a safe station.
You people tell me to do my job
then give me a
Federation rule book
listing all the things
I can't do.
Untie my hands
before you start
to blame me, Mr. O'Brien.
I'm sure no one meant
to blame you, Odo.
Give me the right
to set a curfew.
Let me do more searches
of arriving passengers.
Give me 50 more deputies.
And this station will be
just the way it was
during the occupation.
Say what you like.
It was safer then.
Unless you happened
to be a Bajoran.
I want a complete review
of all security measures
on board this station.
I'll be delighted
to accommodate you.
What do we have from the guard?
He's given us a description
of the two who assaulted him...
A Vulcan female
and a human male
in a Starfleet officer's
uniform.
We're trying to locate anyone
they might have contacted here.
How many ships left the station
during the night?
Only two, sir.
The Bardeezan merchant ship
and a Galador freighter.
What were their destinations?
The Bardeezans went
through the wormhole.
The freighter is operating
on a trade route
between Galador II
and Farius Prime.
I'm guessing these people
wouldn't take Dukat
through the wormhole.
They'd head back to the
Demilitarized Zone with him.
Dax, check the Galador
ship's registry
and make sure it's in order.
Chief, see if you
can identify its warp signature
from our sensor records.
No problem, Commander.
I've got it.
Last known course.
The computer's showing it was
on a bearing 216 mark 177.
As it left our sensor range
it was still heading
for Farius Prime.
Major, send a message
to Farius Prime.
If that ship shows up,
and I doubt that it will
I want to know it right away.
I could send the warp signature
out over subspace.
You could make it
a general transmission.
If it changes course,
someone should spot it.
Do it.
It's a phony.
The Galadorans don't have
any ships in this sector.
The registry is forged.
Doctor, Major, you're with me.
Odo, send a message
to Commander Hudson
at the Volon colony that I'm
moving in his direction
on the assumption
that Dukat will be taken
to the Demilitarized Zone.
Give him the warp signature
of the ship.
Aye, sir.
Commander, we just received
a general subspace transmission
from somewhere
in the Demilitarized Zone.
A group there is taking credit
for the kidnapping of Dukat.
They're calling themselves...
"the Maquis."
Commander, a Klingon freighter
two light-years
from the Demilitarized Zone
has ID'd the warp signature.
The ship did change course,
just as you predicted.
Transmit
their last known coordinates
and heading to us, Chief.
Acknowledged.
Let us know if anyone else
picks up their signature.
Aye, sir.
O'Brien out.
Set a new course, Major.
Yes, sir.
Their heading takes them
into the badlands.
Badlands?
It's a stretch
of the Cardassian border
ships try to avoid.
A lot of plasma storms
in the area.
A few ships have been lost there
in the past year or two.
Sounds like the perfect place
for a hideout.
Excuse me, sir.
What do you plan to do
if we catch up with them?
After all, these Maquis
are Federation colonists.
We're going
to get Gul Dukat back
by any means necessary.
Even if we have to fire
on our own people?
Long-range sensors are picking
up the warp signature.
It leads to an M-Class asteroid.
Take us there.
Scanning the surface.
I've located the ship.
Those are human life signs.
Is there a Cardassian
among them?
No, sir.
Prepare to beam down.
I'm glad to see you had
no trouble finding us, Ben.
It seems that one disaster
after another
keeps bringing us
back together again.