Last time on
Deep Space Nine...
A number of Admirals
at Starfleet Command are worried
the destruction
of the Bok'nor
might jeopardize the treaty.
Oh, are they really?
As the two ranking officers
along the Cardassian border,
we've been asked to assess
the potential risk.
I wish to procure weapons.
I beg your pardon?
Guns, phaser banks,
photon torpedoes...
Shh.
...troop transports,
and a number of
cobalt-thorium devices.
You're a gun runner?
I'm here unofficially
to help you find out
the truth about the Bok'nor.
Why would you want to help me?
Because I already know
the truth.
I've got people out there
killing people, Major.
You suggest I turn
a blind eye to that?
They don't have a right
to defend themselves?
They've crossed the line!
If Starfleet is unwilling
to defend their people...
They chose to live
with the Cardassians!
Well, I didn't!
But I lived with them
for 26 years
before the liberation came.
Every Bajoran lived with them
in constant fear.
I know what those colonists
are going through.
We just received
a general subspace
transmission
from somewhere in the
Demilitarized Zone.
A group there
is taking credit
for the kidnapping
of Dukat.
They're calling
themselves...
"the Maquis."
HUDSON:
I'm glad to see you had
no trouble finding us, Ben.
It seems that one disaster
after another
keeps bringing us
back together again.
And now,
for the conclusion.
You should have seen
the look on your face
when you saw me
standing there, Ben.
I hardly recognized you
without your uniform.
Well, it's been feeling
a little tight lately.
Just like that.
It's just a uniform, Ben.
Is that all it is?
I remember when
you first put it on.
Yes-- graduation day
at the Academy.
We both swore
that we'd be starship captains
by the time we were 30.
And admirals by 40.
Yes.
I think we've both done
pretty well for ourselves.
Yes, we have, haven't we?
But now, I've got
something better.
These settlers, Ben--
if you saw all they
have accomplished
without any help
from the Federation
then you'd fight
along with them.
I don't think so.
HUDSON:
They've traveled out here
to the back of the beyond
and built homes
out of the wilderness.
Now, maybe the Federation
can turn their backs on them,
but I can't.
I'm not asking you to,
but your joining
the Maquis
isn't helping anyone.
Your actions have only
endangered the treaty
and put millions
of lives at risk.
The Federation believes
that it can solve
every problem with a treaty,
but out here, on the frontier,
without the power
of the Federation
to back them up,
a treaty is only
a piece of paper.
Do you have evidence
that the Central Command
has violated the treaty?
Not yet, but we will.
If you're depending
on Gul Dukat for proof,
you're going to be
disappointed.
We'll find out, won't we?
I want him back, Cal.
He's not here.
Then where is he?
I never thought
I'd see the day
when you'd side
with a Cardassian
against me.
Damn it, Cal,
I'm on your side.
You've got a funny way
of showing it, Ben.
I'm trying to stop
you from making
one of the biggest
mistakes of your life.
The Federation
believes in the treaty.
If you destroy it,
Starfleet will
come after you,
and they won't be satisfied
until you're behind bars.
If we work together
to end the violence...
The violence will never end
as long as Central Command
continues to smuggle weapons
to their colonies.
I wish there were
a better way to
handle this thing.
I really do.
Nobody wants peace any
more than the Maquis.
And you're willing
to blow up Cardassian ships
to get it?
The Bok'nor
will never smuggle
weapons again.
And its crew members
won't be returning home
to their families either.
Look, you say
the Central Command
is behind the smuggling.
Fine, let's prove it.
How?
We'll go to Cardassia,
find the evidence
you need to back
up your claim,
and when we do, we'll
take it to the Federation.
No, the Federation
abandoned us.
Told us to take care
of ourselves.
Well, that's what we
intend to do, Ben,
but you--
you could be invaluable to us.
Let us use
your station.
For what?
A maintenance facility
for our ships.
I can't allow that.
Every week, innocent people
are murdered by the Cardassians.
I will not allow those deaths
to go unpunished.
You don't want peace, Cal.
You want revenge.
I prefer to call it retaliation.
I am sorry we won't be
working together, Benjamin.
It would have been nice.
Like... old times.
Commander!
Sorry, Benjamin.
No!
Okay, let's go.
Knowing Ben's temper
when he wakes up,
we won't want to be here.
Come on, let's move out.
Come on, here we go.
Let's go, come on.
Lieutenant, I want to speak with
the Cardassian Central Command.
Then you're in luck.
Legate Parn will be arriving
within the hour.
A Legate?
I feel honored.
While I'm waiting,
I want to speak with Starfleet.
Admiral Necheyev's
already here.
Chief, the Maquis must have
transferred Dukat off their ship
before they reached
that asteroid.
I want to know
where they've hid him.
I can retrace
their warp trail.
See if they met up
with any other ships.
Do it.
Admiral.
Commander, the Cardassian
Central Command
has gone on military alert
in response to the kidnapping
of Gul Dukat.
I'm not surprised.
This Security Chief of yours,
this shape-shifter...
Odo.
Are you sure you
wouldn't be better off
with a Starfleet officer
heading your security team?
Admiral, I have complete
faith in Odo's ability
to do his job.
If you say so, Commander.
I do.
And as for Gul Dukat,
I assure you
we are taking all possible
steps to locate him.
Good. Keep me informed
of your progress.
I will. But, Admiral,
there is a bigger issue
here than rescuing Dukat.
And what is that?
The Maquis.
The Maquis are a bunch
of irresponsible hotheads.
These hotheads are
responsible for the
bombing of the Bok'nor.
I'm aware of that,
Commander.
We never should have allowed
those colonists to remain
on the Cardassian side
of the Demilitarized Zone.
Well, they're there, Admiral,
and they're not leaving.
What about
Commander Hudson?
He's lived with these people.
What's his analysis
of the situation?
I'll... have to ask him.
You do that.
And, Commander,
I want you to find the Maquis.
Talk to them. Remind them
that they're citizens
of the Federation.
That it is imperative
that we preserve
the treaty with
the Cardassians.
A treaty the Cardassians
may not be honoring.
Are you questioning
Federation policy, Commander?
All I know
is that the situation
in the Demilitarized Zone
is deteriorating rapidly.
Personally, I think
you're overstating
the problem.
Establish a dialogue
with the Maquis.
They're still
Federation citizens.
I'm sure they'll
listen to reason.
Good luck, Commander.
"Establish a dialogue."
What the hell does she think
I've been trying to do?
Commander.
Just because
a group of people
belong to the Federation,
that does not mean
that they are saints.
Excuse me.
Do you know
what the trouble is?
No.
The trouble is Earth.
Really?
On Earth, there is no poverty,
no crime, no war.
You look out the window
of Starfleet headquarters
and you see paradise.
Well, it's easy to be
a saint in paradise,
but the Maquis do not
live in paradise.
Out there,
in the Demilitarized Zone,
all the problems
haven't been solved yet.
Out there, there are no saints,
just people--
angry, scared,
determined people
who are going to do
whatever it takes to survive,
whether it meets with the
Federation's approval or not.
Makes sense to me.
Well, I'm glad
someone understands.
Legate Parn's ship just put in
at Docking Bay 5.
Maybe you'd like to give
the same speech to him.
I just might do that.
Odo to Sisko.
Go ahead, Constable.
I think you'd better
get down to Security.
I've caught one
of the Vulcan's accomplices.
I assure you, I had no idea
Sakonna was planning
to kidnap Gul Dukat.
Really? Then perhaps
you could explain
why the two of you
were spending
so much time together.
Surely it's no crime
keeping company
with a beautiful female.
You ought to try it, Odo.
It might improve
your disposition.
Do you expect us to believe
that a Vulcan
would be interested in you
for your lobes?
Vulcans are a species
that appreciate good ears.
Commander,
this is very embarrassing,
having to discuss my personal
life in such surroundings.
Embarrassment is going to be
the least of your problems
unless you tell me what kind
of business arrangement
you had with this woman.
All right, but first
I want to make it clear
that I was led astray
by Sakonna's feminine wiles.
Save the excuses, Quark.
Just tell us what
you were up to.
Sakonna was in the market
for certain items
which I was able to obtain.
At a considerable discount,
I might add.
What items?
We're waiting.
Let's see... where to begin?
She wanted
some deflector shields,
navigational arrays,
maybe a couple hundred
photon torpedoes...
Photon torpedoes!
And pulse cannons,
and some high-energy
disrupters.
Weapons! You sold weapons
to a terrorist group.
I did not. The Pygorians
sold them the weapons.
I merely...
made some introductions.
Besides, I hadn't even heard
of the Maquis until after
Dukat was kidnapped.
I want a complete list
of every weapon she purchased.
Of course,
and if you need someone
to testify against Sakonna
in court,
I'd be more than willing.
Would you?
In a second, and let me know
if there's anyone else
who needs testifying against.
I'll tell you one thing,
Commander.
Sakonna was on a tight clock.
Whatever she needed
those weapons for,
it's going to happen
within the next few days.
Just get me the list.
Sir, I assume
you'll be going out
to search
for Dukat again.
As soon as O'Brien
tells us where to look.
As Chief of Security,
I'd like to go along.
I'll be happy
to have you along.
And one other thing--
how long do I keep him here?
Forever.
Odo...
This isn't funny.
Odo!
This is Legate Parn.
He insisted on
seeing you immediately.
Because my business
here is crucial,
it demands
immediate attention.
And as a member of
the Cardassian Central Command,
I must assure you, Commander,
that what we have to discuss
is most crucial, indeed.
I understand.
I assure you
we are doing everything we can
to find Gul Dukat.
Please, Commander,
your efforts
are appreciated
but unnecessary.
You see, Central Command
has learned that Gul Dukat
was the leader of a small group
of misguided officers
who were funneling
weapons to our colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Then the Maquis
were right.
The Cardassian settlers
are being supplied
by Central Command.
Dukat and the others
were operating entirely
without our knowledge.
Central Command would
never sanction anything
that would
violate our treaty
with the Federation.
We've arrested
Dukat's co-conspirators
and they shall be
dealt with accordingly.
Where does that
leave Dukat?
With the Maquis,
where he belongs.
Are you saying
you don't want him back?
I assume the Maquis
will execute him
for his crimes.
I wouldn't
be surprised.
Well, then I don't see
what difference it makes
whether we do it
or they do it.
How do we know
they won't use Dukat's death
as an excuse to send troops
into the Demilitarized Zone?
I can assure
you, Commander,
that there shall
be no retaliation.
The Cardassians have no
desire to go to war again
with the Federation.
You have my word.
Your word.
Major.
I found our little
talk very enlightening.
I hoped you would.
Unfortunately,
I have some business
to attend to,
but I do hope you'll
take the time
to enjoy the station.
Thank you, Commander,
but I, too,
must attend to my business.
Besides, I am afraid
this place has lost its charm
since the last time
I was here.
I don't believe
a word he said.
Neither do I.
But he did tell me
something
that I needed to know.
Cal was right.
The Central Command
is smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
We just received a report
that three Federation settlers
were killed on Hakton VII.
The Cardassians claim
it was in response
to the destruction
of the Bok'nor.
Which gives the Maquis
a new excuse to strike back.
Chief, what have
you found?
Based on the residual
subspace distortion
of their warp drive,
I was able to plot the course
of the Maquis ship
that took Dukat.
As you can see,
long-range sensors
show no signs
of any other vessels
traveling along that route.
All right, they didn't transfer
him to another ship.
What about a planet?
It's possible.
Their course took them
past five M-Class planets.
I've downloaded
their coordinates into
the Rio Grande's computer.
Good work.
Sisko to Odo.
ODO: Yes, Commander.
Find Dr. Bashir
and meet me immediately
at Landing Pad C.
On our way.
Commander,
you know
there's no reason
to go after Dukat.
You heard Legate Parn.
They don't want him back.
Are you suggesting
we leave him to the Maquis?
Why risk our lives over someone
who's caused so many deaths?
The way I see it,
he's getting exactly
what he deserves.
The Central Command
wants him dead.
That's reason enough
for us to want him alive.
Landing Pad C.
My mind to your mind.
Your thoughts to my thoughts.
My mind to your mind...
MAN:
What is wrong?
It's not working.
That is what's wrong.
This is quite puzzling.
I am unable to establish
a mind-meld.
It would appear
he has the ability
to shield his thoughts.
Simply a matter of discipline.
Now what do we do?
I will rest awhile
and then I will try again.
( Dukat chuckles )
You people really do not
do this very well, do you?
Now, on Cardassia
we know how to
extract information,
though it can get
a bit... unpleasant
and we all know
how the Federation
dislikes unpleasantness.
I share very few sentiments
with the Federation.
Ooh, that's right.
You're renegades,
aren't you?
( laughing )
Or so you'd like to think.
Unfortunately, the Federation
has taught you your lessons
all too well.
You simply lack
the commitment it takes
to do what is necessary.
You tell that to the crew
of the Bok'nor.
Oh, anyone
can blow up a ship.
( derisive laugh )
But to look your enemy
in the eye
knowing you'll
remember his face
for the rest
of your life,
now, that takes...
a stomach much stronger
than you'll ever have.
We'll see
about that.
No.
He's right.
We do not possess
the Cardassian gift
for inflicting pain.
( laughing )
There. You see?
Nor would we want
such a gift.
But we do need to know
when the Central Command
is sending
its next weapons shipment.
So, if it's all the same
to you, Sakonna,
I'll take over
this interrogation.
Then we can find out
just how committed I am.
SISKO: I don't think
anyone's that interested.
Put down your weapons.
We're not here to fight you.
If that is true, then you will
let us go about our business.
I'm not leaving
without Dukat.
Then you're not leaving.
BASHIR:
Look, we're all on
the same side here.
We all want to stop
the arms shipments.
Why not work together?
Will you stop talking
and shoot them?
No, that's not
what we want.
What are you waiting for?
Put down your weapons.
ODO:
Do as he says.
Shoot them!
( yells )
( groans )
( yelling )
Let him go!
I said let him go!
Odo, get these people
secured on the runabout.
With pleasure, Commander.
Except this one.
You mean I'm free to go?
Tell Cal Hudson
I haven't told Starfleet
anything yet.
Tell him, we can still
solve this thing together,
but we're running out of time.
Tell him, I still
have his uniform.
He can have it back
anytime he wants.
Ah.
( door chimes )
Enter.
I just came by to see
how you were doing.
I find a good meal
extremely relaxing,
especially
after a difficult day.
So do I.
Really?
I wonder what else
we have in common.
Very little, I imagine.
( laughing )
Other than the fact
that you have my office.
Tell me,
what's going to happen
with your prisoners?
They'll be tried
for their crimes
under the Federation
Code of Justice.
And if they're
found innocent?
I doubt that they will,
but if they are,
they'll be set free.
How barbaric. In Cardassia,
the verdict is always known
before the trial begins,
and it's always the same.
In that case, why bother
with a trial at all?
Because the people demand it.
They enjoy watching justice
triumph over evil every time.
They find it
comforting.
Isn't there ever a chance
you might try an innocent man
by mistake?
Cardassians don't
make mistakes.
I'll have to remember that.
Commander...
one thing does puzzle me.
Surely the Central Command
was informed of my kidnapping.
They learned about it
almost as soon as it happened.
Then why was I
rescued by you?
Why wasn't the station
surrounded by Cardassian ships
demanding my release?
We did receive a visit
from Legate Parn.
Ah! I'm sure he made some rather
ugly threats on my behalf, hmm?
He said that you
were the one responsible
for smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
That if the Maquis
did not execute you,
then the Central
Command would...
after a comforting trial,
I'm sure.
( sighing )
Well...
it seems my relationship
with the Central Command
has somewhat deteriorated.
I knew this was inevitable
the moment we withdrew
from Bajor.
Are you saying
they blamed you
for the withdrawal?
Ha! There are those
who believe
I should have killed
every last Bajoran
while I had the chance.
Oh, well.
It's too late for that,
I'm afraid.
Commander,
it seems I was mis...
Mistaken about
the arms shipment?
It appears
I was misinformed.
I'm beginning to believe
the Central Command
is indeed smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone
after all.
Then you really
didn't know, did you?
No.
They never bothered
to tell me.
If I help you
stop the smuggling,
will you help me
stop the Maquis?
You have a deal.
I've scheduled
a staff meeting for 0900.
I'll be there.
Commander...
thank you for coming
to my rescue.
I'm sure you would have done
the same for me.
( chuckles )
( sighs )
Constable, do you have
the list of weapons
Sakonna bought from Quark?
I do, and quite a list it is.
Six ship-mounted
high-energy disrupters,
three particle accelerators,
200 photon torpedoes,
and a dozen pulse cannons.
With that kind of firepower,
the Bajorans could have launched
a full-scale assault
on Cardassia.
And lost.
Sounds like the Maquis
have had their fill
of border skirmishes.
They're ready for
something bigger.
According to Quark,
they're planning their
first attack any day now.
Have you been able to make
any headway with Sakonna?
Have you ever tried
to interrogate a Vulcan,
Lieutenant?
No.
Neither had I,
until today.
I wouldn't advise it.
That calm, measured voice
that tells you nothing,
that impassive stare--
it can be quite frustrating.
Perhaps I could
question her.
I don't think so.
Pity.
I like a challenge.
You want a challenge?
Find out how
the Central Command
is getting weapons into
the Demilitarized Zone.
My guess would be by way
of a Xepolite free trader.
Why the Xepolites?
Because the Xepolites
have often served
as intermediaries for us
in the past.
So have the Lissepians.
Ah, but the Xepolites
have never been caught.
The Xepolite ship isn't
responding to our hails, sir.
DUKAT: Of course
they're not responding.
Would you respond
to a Federation hail
if your cargo bays were
full of Cardassian weapons?
Scan their ship, Major.
Let's see what
they're carrying.
Our scanners can't
penetrate their hull.
O'BRIEN:
No wonder.
It's composed of
a sensor-reflective material.
They obviously value
their privacy.
Chief, you and Gul
Dukat remain here.
Major, you're with me.
Let's go see
if it's their privacy
or their guilt they're
trying to protect.
Sorry, Commander,
you can't transport over.
They just raised
their shields.
You're wasting time.
Xepolite ships can reach
a maximum speed of warp 9.8.
If they decide to run,
we'll never catch them.
Well, what would
you suggest?
I would breach their shields
with my phasers
and destroy their bridge.
Killing everyone there.
That's correct.
Then I would lock onto
the ship with my tractor beam
and tow it, and its cargo,
back to the station.
Very simple, very effective.
And needlessly bloody.
Sounds like a Cardassian
plan to me.
Chief, fire a phaser
over their bow.
Let's see if we can
get their attention.
Yes, sir.
( console beeping )
That woke them up.
They're hailing us.
On my monitor, Chief.
I am Drofo Awa,
Hetman of this vessel.
What do you want from us?
I'm Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the United Federation
of Planets.
We believe you're carrying
Cardassian weapons
to their colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Well, then, you believe wrong,
Commander.
My ship is carrying
five kilotons
of Regrean wheat husks,
nothing more.
Five kilotons--
that's a lot of wheat husks.
With your permission,
I'd like to come aboard
and see what that looks like.
Permission denied.
And if there's any attempt
to board my vessel,
I will consider it an act
of piracy. Is that clear?
You can call it
anything you like,
but you're not going anywhere
until we search your ship.
In that case, Commander...
In that case, you will do
exactly as you're told.
You will allow us
free access to your ship
so that we can verify
you are indeed smuggling
Cardassian weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
You will then follow us back
to Deep Space 9
where your cargo
will be confiscated
and you will make
a full confession
detailing everything you know
about smuggling weapons
into the Demilitarized Zone.
Then you will sign
that confession,
after which,
you and your ship will be
allowed on your way.
Is that clear?
I don't understand.
You're a Cardassian.
I'm not just
any Cardassian.
I'm Gul Dukat, Commander
of the Second Order.
You have 15 seconds
to lower your shields
or we'll destroy you.
No, wait!
Ten seconds.
No, it's not that simple!
Seven seconds.
I've already been paid!
Four seconds.
Stop counting!
He's lowering
his shields.
I'll await your arrival,
Commander.
I think you can
handle it from here.
I hope you're happy.
I am a Vulcan.
My emotional state
is irrelevant.
Well, I'm a Ferengi,
and my emotional state
is very relevant,
and right now,
I'm miserable,
and it's all your fault.
You were well paid
for your assistance.
Not well enough.
Look, I know the Cardassians
can't be trusted.
I know the Central Command
would like nothing better
than to destroy
the Federation colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Then you agree
with our position?
Not for a second.
Why not?
Because your position
is illogical.
Do you propose
to lecture me on logic?
I don't want to, but
you leave me no choice.
It all comes down
to the Third Rule
of Acquisition.
You don't know
that one, do you?
I am not well-versed
in Ferengi philosophy.
Remind me to give you
a copy of the Rules.
You never know when
they'll come in handy.
Now, the Third Rule
clearly states
"Never spend more
for an acquisition
than you have to."
Logical,
but I fail to see
how that applies
to my situation.
You want to acquire peace.
Fine. Peace is good.
But how much are you
willing to pay for it?
Whatever it costs.
That's the kind of
irresponsible spending
that causes so many
business ventures to fail.
You're forgetting
the Third Rule.
Right now, peace
could be bought
at a bargain price
and you don't
even realize it.
I find this
very confusing.
( sighs )
Then I'll make it so simple
that even a Vulcan
can understand.
The Central Command has
been caught red-handed
smuggling weapons
to their settlers.
So, every ship
that approaches the
Demilitarized Zone
will be searched.
Without the support
of the Central Command,
the Cardassian settlers
won't be so eager to fight.
You forget the weapons
they already have.
They have weapons.
You have weapons.
Everyone has weapons,
but right now, no one
has a clear advantage.
So, the price of peace
is at an all-time low.
This is the perfect time
to sit down
and hammer out an agreement.
Don't you get it?
Attacking the Cardassians now
will only escalate the conflict
and make peace more expensive
in the long run.
Now, I ask you,
is that logical?
A concealed weapons depot
located within
a civilian population center?
According to Sakonna,
the Maquis are going
to attack the depot
sometime within
the next 52 hours.
But she didn't tell you
on which colony
the depot is hidden.
She says she doesn't know.
How convenient.
I believe her.
Why?
Because Vulcans don't lie?
As a rule, they don't.
They don't blow up
ships either, as a rule.
But let's assume she's
telling the truth.
I take it you haven't
shared this information
with the Central Command?
No, I haven't.
Good.
Because they
would never trust you
to handle
this matter alone.
But they would be able
to tell me where
the weapons depot is located.
Leave that to me.
I may no longer
be a favorite with
Central Command,
but I know
people who are.
In the meantime,
I'll go to Volon III
and try to talk some sense
into the Maquis.
And if you can't?
Don't worry, Dukat.
I said I would stop the Maquis,
and, one way or another, I will.
I've also
been recently informed
that 35 people
had to be hospitalized
on Umoth VIII after eating
from public food replicators.
Sabotage is suspected.
Then from now on,
guards should be posted
at all public replicators
throughout the colonies.
Thank you.
Now, about the new curfew...
( door opens )
Commander Sisko,
what a pleasant surprise.
If you'll just wait a moment,
I'll finish up this meeting
and we can talk privately.
That won't be necessary.
I want everyone to hear
what I have to say.
I don't know
how many of you here
actually belong
to the Maquis.
Those of you who don't
probably have friends who do.
So, please make sure
you pass along
what I'm about to tell you.
There is a treaty
currently in place
with Cardassia
and the Federation.
If you make yourself
an enemy of Cardassia,
you make yourself an enemy
of the Federation.
That is outrageous.
Agreed.
I know the Maquis
is planning to attack
a Cardassian weapons depot.
My advice to them and to you
is to call it off,
because I'll be waiting there,
and I will stop you.
( door opens )
A very rousing speech, Ben.
I suppose my best rebuttal
would be to kill you.
But you won't.
What is this?
Your uniform.
You always were an optimist.
I have every
reason to be.
The way I see it,
now that we've stopped
the shipments
of Cardassian weapons,
there's no longer any need
for the Maquis.
You and I can work together
to reach a peace agreement
with the Cardassian colonies.
It's too late for that.
Is it?
We're in a war here,
and I intend to win it.
I could use
your help, Ben,
and I'm asking you as a friend.
As a friend...
I have to say no.
If you attack
the depot,
you'll have
to get through me first.
I hope not.
I truly hope not.
The Bryma colony--
according to my sources,
that's the location
of the weapons depot.
SISKO:
Then our objective
is simple--
prevent the Maquis ships
from reaching Bryma.
We're going
to have to intercept them
before they're picked up
by the colony's sensors.
Good point.
If the Cardassian settlers
even suspect they might
come under attack,
they'll send a message
to Cardassia asking
for reinforcements.
I don't care how much
the Cardassians care
about the treaty,
if the Maquis launch an assault
against a civilian target,
the Central Command
will have to respond.
We could wind up with
a full-scale war on our hands.
We have to stop the Maquis.
Our runabouts will take up
a defensive position
just outside the Bryma
colony's sensor range.
The best way to
detect incoming ships
would be to hide
a couple dozen sensor probes
in the system's Oort cloud.
That way,
we could spot the Maquis
no matter what route they take.
How many Maquis ships
are we expecting?
According to Sakonna,
they only have two ships
capable of mounting
the weapons she purchased.
So, we'll have three ships,
and they'll have two.
The odds are in
our favor, anyway.
That won't
give us much of an
advantage, Julian.
The colonists are used
to being outnumbered.
They'll fight just
that much harder.
How do you propose
to stop them?
What's that human expression?
"Shoot to kill."
SISKO:
We'll try to stop
them with words,
if possible;
with force, if necessary.
So, if they fire at us,
we have orders
to shoot back.
That's correct.
We'll target their warp engines
and weapons arrays--
try to disable them.
DUKAT: How noble.
I hope the Maquis will be
as obliging to you.
Rio Grande to
Mekong and Orinoco.
How do you read me?
Orinoco here.
You're loud and clear.
Mekong here.
Our communications channel
is fully operational
and secure.
The remote sensor
probes I set up
still haven't detected
any sign of the Maquis ships.
Do you really think
they're coming?
They know we're waiting
for them, after all.
It's possible they changed
the time frame of their attack--
postponed it
a day or a week.
SISKO:
They'll be here.
The longer they wait,
the greater the chance
the weapons depot will be
moved to another location.
O'BRIEN:
Commander, I'm picking up
two Federation ships
headed our way.
Sisko to Hudson.
This isn't going
to work, Cal.
Turn those ships around
before someone gets hurt.
Please, Ben,
don't make me open fire on you.
He's not going to listen.
Initiating
evasive maneuvers.
Signal Niles to
follow my lead.
Right.
Commander, they're
making a run for it.
Lock on tractor beams.
Damn it!
They've got Niles, too.
Let us go, Ben.
You know I can't do that.
Then I suggest you duck.
Fire on their beam emitter.
( console beeping
insistently )
What are you
waiting for?
O'BRIEN:
We're losing tractor lock.
KIRA:
They're breaking away.
Commence firing.
Niles' propulsion system
is down.
He's drifting.
We'll have to
even the odds.
They've hit
our navigational array.
I've lost attitude control.
Attempting to compensate
with manual thrusters.
KIRA: It's not working.
Thrusters are still locked.
Hang on. Chief,
you go after
the Orinoco.
I'll handle Hudson.
O'BRIEN: Right.
Major.
Yes, Chief?
Lower your shields.
We'll beam you
out of there.
They're coming back around.
( console beeping )
It's just you and me, Ben.
I can't let you start a war.
I'm not turning back.
And you're not going forward.
We're hit.
Our photon torpedo tubes
are out.
Switch to phasers.
Come about, heading
115 mark 326.
Got it.
We've taken a direct hit
on our primary fusion core.
Initiating emergency
core shutdown.
The port nacelle is flooded
with ionized deuterium.
We've lost both warp
and impulse engines.
We still have
maneuvering thrusters.
They're coming back around.
Use the phasers.
I can't.
They've knocked out
the power couplings
to our weapons array.
What do we do?
The only thing we can do.
We get the hell out of here.
He's turning away.
Now's your chance-- fire.
It's over, Cal.
For now, anyway.
Next time,
tell Starfleet
to send someone else.
It doesn't feel right, you and I
shooting at each other.
There won't be a next time.
Stand down!
I don't think so, Ben.
He's getting away!
You run now,
I won't be able to protect you.
Starfleet will track you down.
You won't be safe anywhere--
not even in the colonies.
Don't be so sure. I have
a lot of friends here.
Besides, I've got to help
the Maquis finish this thing.
You'll be an outlaw--
a hunted man.
Maybe.
You're throwing away
your entire life.
And beginning a new one.
What are you
waiting for?
He's helpless.
Finish him.
I'm going to miss you, Ben.
You've been a good friend.
So have you.
No!
I thought you were strong,
Commander.
You're not.
You're a fool.
A sentimental fool.
I said I'd stop the
Maquis, and I have,
but I will not
kill a good man
for defending his home.
You disappoint me.
Don't expect me to lose
any sleep over it.
Mr. O'Brien,
when you get a chance,
I could use some help
with these engines.
Yes, sir.
Commander, Gul Dukat
has left the station.
I'm sure he's glad
to be going home.
Chief O'Brien says
that the Orinoco
and the Rio Grande
will be up and running
in a few days.
Thank you, Major.
I just got
a communiqu
from Starfleet
congratulating me
on my good work
and thanking me for preserving
the peace with the Cardassians.
You deserve it.
You prevented a war.
Did I?
Or did I just
delay the inevitable?