Medical Log, supplemental.
Major Kira and I
are returning home
after opening the hospital
on New Bajor
the first Bajoran colony
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Oh...
could you take it for a while?
Sure.
Do you mind
if I listen to some music?
Actually, I do.
I was hoping to meditate
for a few minutes.
Of course.
I didn't know you meditate.
Every day.
I had the opportunity
of studying meditation
with Isam Helewa
when I was at college.
A remarkable fellow.
He sort of took
me under his wing.
I can't tell you how much
I learned from him.
The man was a master
at rhythmic breathing.
You'll have to give me
a few tips sometime.
Gladly.
Oh, and I'd be more
than interested
in learning any Bajoran
meditation techniques
you might like to show me.
We usually just like
to sit...
quietly.
What are you doing?
Bellows breath...
it's a series of quick intakes
followed by one long intake
of air through the nose.
Hold... release.
Increases the energy flow.
It's quite simple.
Let me show you.
How about some music?
Ah. What's your pleasure?
I'm afraid my musical knowledge
is limited to Bajoran composers.
Computer, play us a little
something by Tor Jolan.
You know Tor's work?
Oh, I've made it
a point to listen
to Bajoran music
ever since I arrived.
Really?
Tor strikes me as the best
of the lot, really.
Well, slightly derivative
of the great Boldaric masters
of the last century
but pleasantly diverting.
Hmm, this is nice.
I'm glad we're
finally doing this.
What?
Talking to one another.
Finding common interests.
Burying the hatchet.
Hatchet?
A human expression.
It means that
we're finally putting
past conflicts behind us.
Making way for brand-new ones.
Right.
You know, Nerys...
May I call you Nerys?
Sure.
Even when we weren't
getting along
I've always felt you were
one of the most
interesting women
I've ever met.
I'm very serious.
Thank you, Doctor.
Julian.
Go on, say it.
- Julian.
It was hard for Chief O'Brien,
as well, at first.
We had our problems, too,
but now we're like this.
One minute to the wormhole.
Stand by to drop to impulse.
Would you like
to have dinner sometime?
I, uh, I think you'd
better stick with Dax.
I'm sorry?
Oh!
You thought
that I was trying to...
No, no...
My, my mistake.
But if I thought...
Forget it!
Right.
Take us out of warp.
What's wrong?
The warp field's
not fully collapsed.
I'm showing
a plasma injector leak.
Injector controllers
are locked.
I'm trying to compensate.
Injectors opening,
velocity falling.
What was that?
Initiating emergency
stabilization control.
Are you all right?
A little dizzy.
Yeah, me, too.
I guess we're lucky
to be in one piece.
Oh, we'd better get
Mr. O'Brien to take a...
What the hell?
Where's the station?
What happened to the station?
I have it on long-range sensors.
It's...
orbiting Bajor?
Major...
vessel approaching on an
intercept course, dead ahead.
What is this?
I'm... sorry, ma'am.
We were not informed
you'd left the station.
Who are you?
We were on standard patrol
when your vessel seemed
to appear out of nowhere.
If you will allow
us to withdraw
we will escort you
back to the station.
I was as close to her
as I am to you.
She cannot be an impostor.
But she is.
What is going on here?
Garak!
Yes, my name is Garak.
The question is...
who...
are you?
This... may sound
like an odd question
but... could you tell us
where we are?
This is the Terok Nor station.
The center of authority
for the Bajoran Sector.
"Center of authority."
Whose authority?
The Alliance, of course.
Something is very wrong here.
I think we took a wrong turn
in the wormhole.
Wormhole?
The wormhole to the Gamma...
It's very difficult to explain.
I think it would be best
if we just got back
to our ship and...
No!
I don't think so.
Now, wait a minute.
Don't take that tone
with us, Terran.
Terran?
If you are
who I suspect you are
I'm afraid I can't run the risk
of letting you go.
Take that one below.
Put him to work.
Tell the supervisor
to keep an eye on him.
He won't know the rules.
Move, Terrans! Move!
Intendant!
What is it you need, Telok?
This Terran was caught
trying to stow away
on one of the freighters
leaving the station.
What is your designation?
0413-Theta.
Theta.
Yes, ma'am.
You worked so hard
to earn your theta designation
to earn our trust.
Why do you throw
it away like this?
Reassign him to Lambda.
Send him to the mines.
The mines?
But he should die for this.
We should make
an example of him.
You have made a career
out of setting examples, Garak.
I think you enjoy it too much.
He could never have gotten
on board that ship without help.
This is the third incident
in a month.
At least, allow me
to interrogate him.
Fine.
Interrogate him.
But if he dies
under your interrogation
I will make you my example.
Is that clear?
Very, Intendant.
I'm telling you.
If you don't upgrade the
thorium containment cells
there's going to be an accident,
and I'm not going
to be responsible
for the consequences.
Another worker for you...
a Terran who doesn't know
the rules.
Well!
We'll see to it
that he learns them.
What's your designation?
Bashir, Julian.
Is that a joke?
I don't know.
Is it?
No jokes.
That's my Rule of Obedience
Number 14.
Now, what's your designation?
I don't have a designation.
I don't have a designation,
sir.
Another Rule of Obedience?
I don't have a designation
sir...
I don't have a designation, sir.
Now, why is that?
I don't know.
And frankly, I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
You're here to process ore.
Have you ever done that before?
No, I haven't.
Have you ever worked
in the mines?
No.
Then what have you done?
I've been practicing medicine.
Did you forget Rule of Obedience
Number 14?
It's not a joke.
I am a doctor.
Well, Doctor, don't forget
to scrub before you operate.
Oh, sit down.
You are me, aren't you?
I am Kira Nerys.
That makes two of us.
Where you come from
things are very much
like this, aren't they?
There's a station,
a Bajor, Cardassians
Terrans, Klingons.
The players are all the same
but... everyone seems to be
playing different parts.
You didn't seem
to recognize the Alliance.
No.
Perhaps you'd recognize
the name Kirk.
No, I'm sorry, I don't.
Interesting.
On my side, Kirk is one
of the most famous names
in our history.
Almost a century ago
a Terran starship captain
named James Kirk
accidentally exchanged places
with his counterpart
from your side
due to a transporter accident.
Our Terrans were
barbarians then
but their empire was strong.
While your Kirk
was on this side
he met a Vulcan named Spock
and somehow had
a profound influence on him.
Afterwards, Spock rose
to Commander in Chief
of the Empire by preaching
reforms, disarmament, peace.
It was quite a remarkable
turnabout for his people.
Unfortunately for them
when Spock had completed
all his reforms
his Empire was no longer
in any position
to defend itself against us.
Us?
The Alliance,
the historic coming-together
of the Klingons
and the Cardassians.
And Bajor is a part
of this Alliance?
We'd been under Terran
occupation for decades.
When we were freed
we petitioned
for entry and were accepted.
We have become quite
an influential power
within the Alliance.
Is it similar at all
on your side?
No.
My Bajor is not so fortunate.
I'd be very interested
to hear more about it.
I can't stay here.
You must see that.
Well, you see,
that's part of the problem.
I don't know
how to send you back.
But more than that...
there's a...
a certain protocol
I'm supposed to follow.
I'm not sure what you mean.
After the first crossover
we were afraid others might come
to interfere in our affairs.
It was decided then
that if it ever happened again
we would promptly dispose
of anyone who appeared
from your side.
I see.
Unlike my First Officer,
Mr. Garak
I have no taste for violence.
I regret using it,
even when it seems necessary.
I know exactly what you mean.
You do, don't you?
I know you don't want to kill me
and you're searching
for a good reason not to.
Got any ideas?
My side needs what you have...
a strong Bajor.
If you knew the struggles
we've been through
to rebuild our world...
Who's to say you won't
influence us this time?
Me?
My side once changed
the course of your history.
Well, maybe this time
your side can change mine.
Maybe you can teach me
what I need to know
to become the leader
of Bajor, as you have.
That appeals to me.
If I can find a way back.
But... I will have
to kill your friend.
No, don't.
If you knew him...
He's an arrogant Terran
who's lived
a privileged life on my side.
Let him see how
the other half lives.
No, it's too dangerous.
The Cardassians and the Klingons
would never allow it.
Are you the leader
of this sector or not?
Oh!
You know how to manipulate me.
I know how I'd feel
in your place.
I wouldn't give a damn
what the Cardassians
or the Klingons thought.
You're right.
I don't.
Find this...
attractive young woman
some quarters.
Kira Nerys
I'll call for you later.
The Intendant informed me
you'd be inspecting
the facilities.
If there's anything
I can explain...
No. I've worked
in ore processing, myself.
Is my Terran friend
behaving himself?
They all behave themselves
when I'm in charge.
Good.
Good. If you don't mind,
I'll speak with him.
Huh?
Are you all right?
Learning a new trade.
Do you have any idea
what happened?
Have you ever heard
of a Starfleet Captain
named James Kirk?
Kirk?!
Oh, of course...
the transporter accident.
Read about it at the Academy.
So, that's where we are.
That's where we are.
Is there another me here?
Not on this station.
I haven't found Dax or Sisko.
O'Brien's been tinkering around
with the machines.
Major, if Kirk got here
by transporter
do you think we could
get back the same way?
I don't know anything
about transporters. Do you?
Well, no one knows
more about transporters
than Chief O'Brien.
Well, our Chief O'Brien.
Who knows about theirs?
It's worth a shot.
Talk to him.
I'll try to see if I can find
anyone else who might
be willing to help.
Yeah.
You certainly are the spitting
image of the Intendant...
just as they said.
Hello, Quark.
You know my name.
Quark runs a bar
on my side, too.
Really?
I hope I'm doing
decent business.
Got to be better than here.
The Alliance taxes
are killing me.
What can I get you?
The Intendant likes
a hot jumja tea
this time of day.
Well, I'm not her
but that does sound good.
Coming up.
So, uh, are we close friends
on your side?
Yeah, as a matter
of fact, we are.
On my side, Quark does
me a lot of favors.
Favors?
The Quark I know...
well, he just has the ability
to get things done
when no one else can.
You know what I mean?
Sometimes he even
gets things done
behind the backs
of the security people.
What kind of favors
do you ask him for?
Oh, all sorts of favors, like...
getting me things I need...
Such as?
Well, for instance, a
transporter for a few hours.
Didn't I hear somewhere
that a transporter was involved
in the first crossover?
That's right.
Do you have a way back
to your side, Major?
Under the right circumstances,
I might be willing
to help you get access
to a transporter.
Look, Quark.
I don't have a strip
of gold-pressed latinum
so don't even think about it.
Gold-pressed what?
What is it you want?
The ability to send others
across to your side.
Others?
What others?
That's not important.
Look, I can't open
a revolving door to...
Quark!
Mr. Garak!
What can I get you today?
Drinks are always
on the house for you.
You must come with us.
Is there a problem?
Yes, a slight problem.
You've been helping Terrans
escape from the station.
Me? I'm a simple barkeep
and a coward.
I assure you, I don't stick
my neck out for anyone.
That's not what the Terran
we caught this morning
told us during
his interrogation.
This is all a misunderstanding.
Hmm...
I assure you...
I shall miss him.
He always let me win at dabo.
Bartender!
He's just been arrested.
Arrested?
What a damned shame.
Who wants a drink on the house?
Here, I do!
Two!
Just give me the bottle.
Don't be stingy!
Here.
Miles O'Brien.
I know you, on my side.
Yeah?
Actually, we're best friends.
You and me?
That's right.
What am l...
some kind of doctor, too?
No, you're Chief of Operations
of this station.
Me? Go on.
It's true.
Chief of Operations.
Looks like you know your way
around machines.
Well, I know some things.
What else is he like,
this Chief of Operations?
Ah, he's married.
He has a five-year-old daughter.
He's one of the most
decent men I know.
We fought our way
out of a few scrapes together.
I admire him a great deal.
Sounds like he got
the lucky draw
between me and him.
Have you ever done much
work on transporters?
Me?
Yeah, some.
Why?
Well, the Chief O'Brien I know
is an expert
in transporter technology.
I wouldn't call myself
an expert
but I know as much
as any Terran.
I hope that'll be enough.
Enough for what?
We think that a transporter
will help us get
back to our side.
What?
You're filling me up
with this stuff
just to get me to help you,
is that it?
No, everything
I've told you is the truth.
I don't know you.
I'm not your friend.
I'm not your friend!
Meal break is over.
You're wanted in the bar.
Look, if I don't finish here...
You're wanted
in the bar by Mr. Sisko.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Yes.
Look at this.
Do you believe it?
She called me all the way
from the Fowla system
to see you.
Not only do you look like her,
you have the same temper.
You and your friends
don't seem
like the other Terrans
I've seen here.
The Intendant honors me
with a ship and a crew.
I honor her
by collecting duties...
of a sort... from vessels
that pass in this direction.
And why do you deserve
this special treatment?
I suppose because I amuse her
and she's not easily amused.
And it seems
that you amuse her, too.
You wanted to see me, Mr. Sisko.
Hello, Smiley.
How are you?
It's Miles, Mr. Sisko.
I don't like "Miles."
That's why I named you Smiley.
Are they treating you okay,
Smiley?
Just fine.
What do you need?
You don't like me,
do you, Smiley?
Not really, Mr. Sisko.
Ah, and you're not afraid
to show it, are you?
I suppose that's why
I like you so much.
My impulse driver coil
isn't operational.
Take care of it.
I've got a serious problem
in ore processing
that's got to be fixed...
I don't care what's going on
in ore processing.
Fix my engine.
Hmm?
Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead.
I'd like to discuss
your recent mission.
Would you please report
to my quarters?
There she is.
Have you met my friend,
Benjamin Sisko, my dear?
Tell us...
is there another one
of him on your side?
Yes, there is.
Is he as loyal and true as mine?
He's a good man.
Oh, I'm sorry he didn't
come with you.
Wouldn't that have been
something, Benjamin?
Two of you by my side.
I need to check my ship.
Benjamin!
Did I hurt your feelings?
I never had any to hurt,
Intendant.
Now, what is this I hear
about you wanting a transporter?
Quark mentioned something
about it
during his interrogation.
I did ask him about
a transporter, that's true.
But why?
Well, you know I'm looking
for a way back.
A transporter was responsible
for the first crossover.
And if you had come to me,
I would have told you
all transporters
were redesigned afterwards
to make sure the same thing
would never happen again.
It won't work.
So... why didn't you come to me?
You're very busy.
You don't trust me.
I'm... a little afraid of you.
Then you fear yourself.
I don't want your fear.
I want your love.
If you can't love me, who can?
Don't be in such a hurry to go.
I'm glad you're here.
There is so much we can learn
from one another.
Intendant, Garak is here
with the prisoner.
Send him in.
He's made a full confession
and implicated two others,
who have been arrested.
Quark.
I have always liked you,
you know that.
I have nothing but respect
for you, Intendant.
I'm so sorry.
You did it because you felt
sorry for these Terrans.
You hate to see them suffer,
just as I do.
Yes, Intendant.
But where would we be
without them?
Who would perform the labor
for the Alliance?
A quick death.
Don't make him suffer anymore.
No, Intendant, please.
I made a mistake.
Have mercy!
No, please!
I've planned a party
for us tonight.
What shall we wear?
Lovely.
I do admire
a well-tailored gown.
What are you doing
in my quarters, Garak?
She'll never let you leave,
you know.
Can't you tell?
She's in love.
What are you talking about?
In love with you, my dear.
She's all atwitter about you.
Can't talk about anyone else.
You're the perfect gift
for the girl who has everything.
She's taken you into her heart
like a Drathan puppy lig
left on her doorstep.
Who else could she share
her deepest secrets with
tell her troubles to,
trust with her life?
All you have to do is take
a look at the guard outside
to see how much she trusts me.
I arranged the guard.
Oh, she trusts you.
As much as she trusts anyone.
So, who better to betray her?
You're taking quite a risk
coming to me like this.
True career advancement
requires risk.
Consider my offer carefully,
my dear.
She'll never let you go.
I will.
If you want to leave,
you'll assist me.
How?
By taking her place.
What?
Tomorrow morning,
she will be gone.
Gone?
She will be gone.
Please, don't make me use
some foolish euphemism.
You will assume her place
as Intendant and announce
that your counterpart
from the other side
has returned
to wherever she came from.
In a few weeks,
you will step down
to embark on a spiritual journey
to explore your pagh
or whatever.
And I will take your place
as Intendant.
What about my friend?
The good Doctor.
Yes, he'll be taken off
the station
and treated
to as much hospitality
as we Cardassians can offer
until you resign.
And then you can be
happily reunited.
Oh, I've made arrangements
with his supervisor
that, if you should decide
to decline my offer
tomorrow, it will be
your Doctor friend
who will be gone.
We've got to get out
of here tonight.
Why?
What's happened?
I don't have time to explain.
Just watch your back.
You're in danger.
Why my back?
What kind of danger?
We've got to find a way
back to the runabout.
And then where do we go?
The Alliance controls
the entire Quadrant.
There's still
a wormhole out there
they don't know anything about.
Now, I'm not sure whether
it'll get us back or not.
All I know is,
we can't stay here any longer.
How are we supposed to get
past their security?
I'm trying to find some help.
I've heard Quark has helped
some Terrans escape.
No, it's too late for Quark.
Stay alert.
If our chance comes,
there won't be much warning.
Sisko.
Tell her I'm busy.
I have something
important to tell you.
I'm listening.
I have valuable information
and I want something
in exchange.
You've gone into business
for yourself, have you?
All I want is to get
off this station.
I want my runabout back.
And you expect me to help you?
She'll have my head.
Or something else.
Not if you save her life.
Her life?
Garak is planning
to kill her... tonight.
That's it?
That's the valuable information?
Garak has been trying to kill
her since the day he got here.
He wants me to take her place.
Well, now...
that's more creative
than he usually gets.
I wouldn't worry about it.
What kind of a man are you?
You're disturbing my nap.
The Benjamin Sisko I know
would never sell his soul
and allow himself to become
part of this tyranny
against his own people.
Terrans don't have souls.
We don't believe in them.
Well, what do
Terrans believe in?
Raising their children
to dig ore out of the mines
for the Alliance?
I worked in the mines, too,
till I was old enough
to start fighting
for my freedom.
What do you care
about Terrans' freedom?
I care about freedom.
What I don't understand
is why you don't care.
Why the only one
on this station I have met
who seemed to give a damn
was a Ferengi toad named Quark.
You're looking in the wrong
place for a hero, ma'am.
I've made the best
of a bad life for my crew.
That's my contribution.
Yes, you charmed
your way out of the mines
but you and I both know
you're no less a victim
than anyone else here.
My dear...
how breathtaking
you look tonight.
I do hope you'll
save a dance for me
later this evening.
After four years
as a personal guard
for the House of Duras
I was ready to do anything
to get out of there.
You never knew if Lursa
and B'Etor were going to be...
Clumsy fool!
Stupid Terran pig.
What's wrong, Terran?
Lost your nerve?
Afraid to die today, eh?
Get out of my sight.
The Intendant!
Intendant, you look lovely.
Intendant,
what is your pleasure?
Play something bright.
I'm in a happy mood.
You're not accustomed
to this workload
are you, Doctor?
You have much to learn.
It's a shame
this is going to be
your last night on the job.
Engineering, we have
a thorium leak down here!
Release the security locks!
Establish security fields
on all the levels
above and below.
Station guards
at all turbolifts.
Okay, over here.
This way!
He must have gone
below the deck...
You three in back,
come with me.
O'Brien.
You've got to help me.
I don't see you.
You're not here.
I'm just trying to seal
this thorium leak.
Look, I don't know my way around
these conduits, but you do.
My O'Brien does.
Uh-uh.
Just tell me where
the runabout pads are.
I know you, Miles O'Brien.
Somewhere inside of you,
there is a shred of decency.
There has to be.
I am a decent man.
I just... I just...
You don't understand.
I can't help you.
I can't.
They'll kill me.
You're already dead.
I'm sorry you don't see that.
The life inside
every human being here...
every Terran...
died a long time ago.
That's not the right way.
Just tell me one thing.
Is there room
on your ship for me?
You want us to take you with us?
I have no reason to stay here.
Starfleet would probably have
a big problem with that.
To hell with them.
Let's go.
Stop right there!
Intendant.
The new Terran killed
the shape-shifter
and O'Brien tried
to help him escape.
This is my fault
for listening to you.
For keeping him alive
in the first place.
I know very little
about where you come from
but, from what I've heard
I think your kind
has a lot to learn.
We've got a lot to learn?
What a laugh.
Quiet!
On this side,
Terran workers do not speak
to their superiors
as you do.
They certainly
do not murder them.
He was the only one
of his kind...
the man you killed.
Do you realize that?
He is irreplaceable.
No one ran that operation
as efficiently as he did.
No one kept order
among the workers as he did.
This is my reward...
for treating you Terrans
with the least bit of respect.
Very well.
I can learn from my mistakes.
You want to set an example,
Garak.
Use him.
Set an example for all Terrans.
Let him die, slowly, in public
view on the Promenade.
Let his pleas for mercy
echo through the corridors
for all Terrans to hear.
Intendant...
Another word from you, and you
will die right beside him.
And you...
O'Brien...
you tinkerer and putterer
and fixer of broken things
you've been
the perfect theta for years.
What could possibly
have gotten into you?
What were you thinking?
Do you want an answer,
Intendant?
Yes.
This man...
this man is a doctor
where he comes from
and there's an O'Brien there,
just like me
except he's some kind
of high-up Chief of Operations.
They're Terrans.
Can you believe that?
Maybe it's a fairy tale
he made up
but it started me thinking
how... how each of us
might have turned out
if history had been
just a little different.
I wanted him
to take me with him
because, whatever it's like
where he's from
it's got to be better than this.
There's got to be something
better than this.
Not for you, Mr. O'Brien.
Oh, he's going to be
taking you with him...
just not exactly where you
thought he would be taking you.
No, I don't think so.
Have you lost your mind?
No.
I didn't lose it.
I just... changed it.
Go, go!
She's never going
to let you get away.
She'll track you down
no matter how long it takes.
You may want to consider
following us back to our side.
I've got the feeling
I might not fit in
very well over there.
We'll stay one step
ahead of the law.
Don't worry about us.
Maybe we can stir up
some things on this side.
You're still welcome
to come with us.
I might have something
to stay for now.
If you have room on your ship
for me, Mr. Sisko.
I can always use
a good tinkerer and putterer.
You're with me, Smiley.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Disengage the docking clamps.
Confirmed.
Firing thrusters.
Thrusters engaged.
Taking us straight to impulse.
Impulse engines on line.
45 seconds to the wormhole.
I'm still reading
a plasma injector leak
from the warp core.
Yeah, I'm hoping that leak
takes us back
where we came from.
I'm matching
speeds and attitude
with our last time through.
Klingon cruiser approaching.
Shields are down to 60 percent.
Forty.
Ten seconds to the wormhole.
We're hit.
Hold on.
Anything?
The search vessels
picked up
their warp signature traces.
There was also
an indication of a plasma leak.
But no wreckage?
Nothing.
Reading elevated neutrinos.
Something's coming
through the wormhole.
I can't believe it.
It's them.
Benjamin.
They're showing damage
to their deflector grids.
Put them on screen, Mr. O'Brien.
We've got ships
from here to New Bajor
out looking for you.
Where have you been?
Through the looking
glass, Commander.
It's good to be back.