NARRATOR: Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
If you could do any
science project you wanted to,
anything at all...
Visit the Gamma Quadrant?
We've never heard
of the Jem'Hadar.
Then you've been fortunate.
Negotiations with the Dominion
can be a
dangerous thing.
( yells )
The Dominion will
no longer stand by
and allow ships from your side
to violate our territory.
KEOGH:
Starfleet's orders are simple.
Traffic through the wormhole
will be suspended
until the Odyssey
can investigate
the Jem'Hadar's threat.
What about Benjamin
and the others?
Don't worry, Lieutenant.
Commander Sisko's return
is a top priority.
If you're going to try
to rescue them
then we're coming with you.
( roaring )
( yelling )
Here they come.
Major, one of
the Jem'Hadar ships
is making a direct
run at the Odyssey.
The Jem'Hadar wanted us
to escape, didn't they?
You have no idea
what's begun here.
She'll be back.
The question is
who she'll bring with her.
If the Dominion
comes through the wormhole
the first battle
will be fought here
and I intend
to be ready for them.
And now, the continuation.
( sighs )
We're in trouble,
people.
We've run seven simulations
and they all come out the same.
The Jem'Hadar
overwhelm our defenses
and board the station
within two hours.
Two hours doesn't even
give us time
to get reinforcements
from Bajor.
There must be something
we overlooked.
Major, I'm the last one
to say it's hopeless
but given DS9's
structural limitations
our available power supply
and the difficulty of defending
a stationary target
against a heavily
armed mobile force
I'd say two hours is optimistic.
Well, regardless of the time
the casualties
would be appalling.
All right, let's say we let
them board the station.
That still doesn't mean
we have to surrender.
What are you suggesting?
We can, uh...
we can hide in the conduits,
set up booby traps
prepare ambushes...
try and hold out
until we can get
reinforcements.
We can try,
but I don't think
there'd be
much of a station left
by the time they got here.
That leaves us
with two options--
abandon the station
and make a stand on Bajor.
Or... collapse the entrance
to the wormhole.
No, I want a third alternative.
I cannot believe
that we can't...
( console beeping demandingly)
Some kind of large subspace
surge has just activated
our security sensors.
Where is it?
Bearing 148
mark 215.
Distance 300 meters.
300 meters?
That's almost inside
our shield perimeter.
From the intensity
in the harmonic signature
it could be
a cloaked ship,
but I've never seen an energy
dispersal pattern like this.
It's too close for comfort,
whatever it is.
Red Alert.
Raise shields.
Energize phaser banks.
Stand by to lock
photon torpedoes.
The energy
signature's fluctuating.
It's de-cloaking.
It's definitely
a Federation starship,
but I've never seen
that design before.
A Federation ship
with a cloaking device?
It's hailing us.
On screen.
Hello, Major.
Sorry to startle you,
but I wanted
to test the Defiant's
cloaking device.
The Defiant?
I've brought back a little
surprise for the Dominion.
Officially, it's classified
as an escort vessel.
Unofficially,
the Defiant's a warship--
nothing more, nothing less.
I thought Starfleet
didn't believe in warships.
Desperate times breed
desperate measures, Major.
Five years ago, Starfleet
began exploring the possibility
of building a new
class of starship.
This ship would have
no families, no science labs
no luxuries
of any kind.
It was designed
for one purpose only--
to fight and defeat the Borg.
The Defiant was a prototype.
The first ship
in what would have been
a new Federation
battle fleet.
So what happened?
The Borg threat
became less urgent.
Also, some design flaws
cropped up
during the ship's
shakedown cruise
so Starfleet decided
to abandon the project.
What sort of design flaws?
You'll have complete access
to the ship evaluation reports,
but to put it simply,
it's overgunned
and overpowered
for a ship its size.
During battle drills,
it nearly tore itself apart
when the engines were tested
at full capacity.
And this is the ship
that Starfleet sends us
to fight off an attack
by the Dominion?
We're not going to fight
the Dominion, Major
at least, not yet anyway.
Our mission is to take the
Defiant into the Gamma Quadrant
and try to find the leaders
of the Dominion, the Founders.
We have to convince them
that the Federation
does not represent
a threat to them.
What if they
don't believe us?
That's why I asked
for the Defiant.
She may have flaws,
but she has teeth,
and I want the Dominion to know
that we can and will defend
ourselves, if necessary.
( door opens )
I've posted two
security officers
at the Defiant's
docking port, sir.
No one will get near
the cloaking device
without us knowing
about it.
ODO:
I wasn't informed
about any special
security arrangements.
The security arrangements
were by my request
to protect
the cloaking device.
A few introductions
are in order.
This is
Subcommander T'Rul
from the Romulan Empire.
She's here to operate
the cloaking device
which her government
so kindly loaned us
for this mission.
Romulan interests will be
served through cooperation,
and my role is to keep
unauthorized personnel
away from the cloaking device.
May I present my officers.
This is Major Ki...
Thank you,
but I know their names
and I'm not here
to make friends.
( door opens, closes )
Charming.
Well, I am here
to make friends.
I'm Lieutenant Commander
Michael Eddington
Starfleet Security.
Major Kira Nerys.
Odo, Head of
Station Security.
May I ask what your function
is here, Commander?
SISKO:
There will be a complete
mission briefing
at 1800 hours,
but be prepared
to depart the station
at 0700 tomorrow morning.
Dismissed.
You needn't brace yourself
to give me
unpleasant news, Commander.
I'll save you
the trouble.
I've been relieved
as Chief of Security.
( sighs )
Odo, wait!
You've not been relieved.
You're still in charge
of all non-Starfleet security
matters aboard this station.
And what about matters
that are Starfleet?
In those areas, you
coordinate your efforts
with Commander Eddington.
"Coordinate" is
another way of saying
I'll report to him.
I'm sorry, Odo.
This wasn't my idea.
I'm sure it wasn't.
You were just
following orders.
An order I strongly
disagreed with.
I did everything
I could to fight this.
I even took it
to the Chief of Starfleet
Security herself,
but the decision
was final.
May I ask why?
There were some concerns
about several recent
security breaches.
( exhales sharply )
If I was given
the authority I asked for
instead of being tied
to Starfleet regulations
there wouldn't have been
any security breaches.
Odo, your resistance to
following Starfleet regulations
is part of the problem.
Well, I think there might be a
simpler explanation, Commander.
I think Starfleet
decided to bring in
someone they could trust--
someone besides
"the shape-shifter."
This is not
a racial issue, Odo.
I understand
how you must
feel, and I...
Commander.
I don't require
your understanding.
My resignation will be
logged within the hour.
Hey, hey, hey--
I thought you
were unpacking.
I am.
I mean, I was.
But I just kept looking
at the replicator and...
And you just had to have
some I'danian
spice pudding.
You know, I still can't believe
I couldn't get a decent bowl
back on Earth.
That didn't stop you
from ordering it
at every replicator you saw.
So...
is it good to be home?
Yeah.
I can't wait to sleep
in my own bed again.
Whew.
I wonder when that happened.
What?
When did I start thinking
of this Cardassian monstrosity
as home?
I think it happened...
last Thursday.
Around 1700 hours--
when you took
all of this stuff
out of storage
back on Earth.
I... Careful...
That's a 2,000-year-old
Yoruba mask,
and that "stuff" is one
of the finest collections
of ancient African art...
You'll ever see.
I know.
And I also know how much
it means to you.
But, to me,
this will always be
the stuff in your library...
at home.
When you took it
out of storage
so you could
bring it here
it meant that Earth
wasn't home anymore.
This was.
SISKO:
So...
what do you think?
Perfect.
Odo.
There you are.
I just finished talking
to the
provisional government,
and they want you to go with us
to the Gamma Quadrant tomorrow
to act as an official
Bajoran representative.
I'm no diplomat.
I know.
That's why they
want you to go.
If we do locate the Founders
we're going to need
more than diplomacy.
We're going to need
to size them up
see what kind
of threat they pose
to Bajor, analyze...
You're the military
expert, Major, not me.
And I doubt
that the provisional
government contacted you
and asked for my presence
on this mission.
If I'm not mistaken
this is a misguided attempt
to make me feel better.
Maybe it is.
Maybe I'm your friend.
And maybe I want you to see
that you are still
needed here...
no matter what some idiot
Starfleet admiral might think.
The Defiant leaves at 700 hours.
I'm a little confused,
Commander.
You want me to go with you
to the Gamma Quadrant
to help you locate
the Founders.
See? It's not
so confusing after all.
You're joking with me,
aren't you?
Having a little fun
with Quark.
I'm quite serious.
You can't be.
I'm not a diplomat
or an explorer
or a tactical officer
or whatever else you
might need on this trip.
Now, if you need a caterer,
I'd be happy to loan you
a new replicator
that I just got...
Eight months ago
you helped the Nagus
establish a trade agreement
with the Karemma, uh--
tulaberry wine, I believe.
The Karemma are
part of the Dominion.
A minor part--
a very minor part.
They might still
be able to help us
make contact
with the Founders.
Since you're experienced
in dealing with the Karemma,
it seems to me that you're
the logical person...
Actually, my brother Rom
did most of the talking.
I think he'd be better suited
for this mission.
Not Rom-- you.
But why?
Rom only has a son
to think about.
I have a business.
You.
I'm sorry, Commander,
but I must refuse.
My last experience
with the Jem'Hadar
was not a pleasant one
and I have no intention
of repeating it.
Now, there's no way you can
legally force me to do this.
( thump )
The scepter of the Grand Nagus.
I had a chance to discuss
this mission with him
on my way back from Earth.
He seemed to agree with me.
Unless peaceful contact
can be established
with the Founders
business opportunities
in the Gamma Quadrant
might suddenly dry up.
He also agreed with me
that you
are the perfect man
to help me.
I don't believe it.
Which is why he sent this along.
He thought it might convince you
of the high value
he holds
for the success of this mission.
Now...
are you going to defy
the wishes of the Grand Nagus
himself?
No, no... of course not.
I'm happy to serve the Nagus
any way I can.
Thanks, Quark.
I knew I could count on you.
Yeah.
Quark?
Aren't you forgetting something?
Oh.
( door opens, closes )
I just thought
you'd like to know.
The Defiant will be
ready at 0700 hours.
Did it pass
the Chief's inspection?
Does anything?
His maintenance list
is as long as this table.
But he did say it will
take us where we're going.
And back, I hope.
Well, he said
that was up to you.
I'd never have volunteered
for this mission
if I didn't think we had
a chance of coming back.
How many times did
Curzon tell you
never volunteer for anything?
As I recall, Curzon broke
that rule a few times himself.
And regretted it every time.
This is different.
I'd be regretting it even more
if we just waited around
for an invasion.
If I know Starfleet,
they must have run
at least 200
probability studies
on this mission of ours.
So what are the odds
of us succeeding?
Slim.
But better odds
than fighting off
a Jem'Hadar assault
on this station.
And if the station falls,
then Bajor falls
and I will not let that happen.
You know, after Jennifer died
I never thought I would
see you this passionate
about something again.
Two months ago, I would
have agreed with you.
Then I went back to Earth
and I spent all
those weeks debriefing
at Starfleet Headquarters.
And I...
I used to get a thrill
just walking into that building.
I'd look around at the admirals
and think, "One day,
that's going to be me.
"One day, I'm the one
that's going to be making
the big decisions."
Curzon always thought
that was very funny.
Did he?
What I mean is
he could never see a set of
admiral stars on your collar.
He thought that just
making the decisions
would never satisfy you.
You had to implement them--
see the results,
face the consequences.
Curzon always thought
you were the kind of man
who had to be
in the thick of things--
not behind some desk
at Headquarters.
He was a smart old man,
wasn't he?
He'd like to think so.
You'd better get
a good night's sleep.
I was just about to say
the same thing to you.
I'll see you
in the morning, Benjamin.
BASHIR:
The medical database
is practically nonexistent.
I've downloaded
as many of my files
from the station as I can
but this ship
simply wasn't designed
to handle many casualties.
Do the best you can,
and let's hope we don't
have to put your new
database to a test.
Yes, sir.
Quark's settling
into his quarters
and asked me
to relay to you
his profound
disappointment
in the accommodations,
and to inform you
that he could
get you in touch
with several reputable
interior decorators
for a modest fee.
I'll take his offer
under advisement.
Stand by to get underway.
Tactical and communications
are ready, sir.
Navigation and operations,
ready.
Weapons ready.
Impulse engines
on-line.
Warp power available
at your command.
Very well.
Seal the airlock,
release docking clamps, aft...
O'BRIEN:
Just a moment, sir.
There's someone in the airlock.
It's Odo.
Sisko to Odo.
Is there a problem, Constable?
No, Commander. I would like
permission to come aboard.
I'm here at the request
of the Bajoran government.
Permission granted.
Thank you, sir.
Dax, we'll have to arrange some
quarters for the Constable.
I'll do it, sir.
I need to go down to what is
laughingly called the Sick Bay.
Thank you, Doctor.
O'BRIEN:
Odo's aboard, sir.
The airlock's clear.
Release docking clamps.
Aft thrusters at one quarter.
Port and starboard
at station keeping.
We've cleared the station.
Lay in a course
to the wormhole.
I want to cloak as soon as
we reach the Gamma Quadrant.
Understood.
Course laid in, sir.
Engage.
The cloaking device
is operating
within normal
parameters.
Set course for
the Karemma system.
Warp 7.
DAX:
Aye, sir.
Engage.
QUARK:
Odo!
( groans )
( sighs in exasperation )
Is this the best
you can do?
I'm afraid so.
Most of the crew quarters
don't have life supports yet.
Besides, I think
we'd all feel a bit better
with someone here
to watch over Quark.
I take that
as a personal insult, Doctor.
You should.
Now, I think I'll
let you two bunkmates
get more comfortable.
Am I glad
to see you.
I have been stuck
down here in
this miserable hole
ever since
I came on board.
Bunk beds!
No view.
And I can't tell
you what came out
of that replicator when
I asked for synthehol.
So...
what's your role in
this little adventure?
Providing security,
no doubt.
Well, of course you are.
I mean, why else
would you be here?
I can tell you, I
feel much safer now
just knowing
you're along
because I know...
I have been holding
this shape for 16 hours.
I have to revert back
to my liquid state
but I don't want you to watch
and gawk at me!
I understand, completely.
This is a very
private moment
and I won't interfere.
This won't be so bad...
( roars )
I have no interest
in speaking to you
or in listening to
your witless prattle!
So stay out of my way
or you'll regret
the day you ever met me!
Commander,
long-range sensors
have picked up two Jem'Hadar
warships directly ahead.
They're heading
this way at warp 5.
How close will
they pass us?
100,000 kilometers.
That's well within range
of their weapons, Commander.
Should I alter course?
No, we need to know if they can
see through the cloaking device
and this is
as good a time as any.
Maintain course
and speed.
Red Alert.
Aye, sir.
Here they come.
They'll pass us
in five seconds.
On screen.
Track them.
O'BRIEN:
They're continuing
on their original heading.
No indication that they saw us.
( console beeping )
Wait a minute.
They're changing
course.
Heading this way.
They must have seen us.
They're powering
their weapon systems.
Prepare to de-cloak,
lock phasers on the lead ship...
No! We may not have
been detected.
Explain.
A cloaked ship radiates
a slight subspace variance
at warp speeds.
I never heard that.
It's not something we've
been eager to reveal.
I suggest dropping
out of warp.
That will eliminate
the variance.
When they reach
our position
they'll find nothing.
Do it.
All stop.
Commander,
they're sweeping the area
with some kind
of an anti-proton scan
and they're being
very thorough about it.
Will an anti-proton scan
penetrate the cloak?
O'BRIEN:
That's a good
question.
I'm not sure.
( console beeps )
They're getting closer.
O'BRIEN:
Commander.
The Defiant's power signature
is unusually high
for a ship this size.
The cloaking device
may not be masking everything.
Cut main power.
The other one
has broken off its search.
It's headed this way.
Stand by weapons and shields.
They've gone into warp...
and resumed
their original course.
The first thing to go right
in the Gamma Quadrant
in a long time.
Let's hope it's not the last.
SISKO:
Ship's Log, Stardate 48212.4.
We have arrived
at the Karemma home world
and opened talks with one
of Quark's business partners
in an effort to contact
the Founders of the Dominion.
The Grand Nagus himself
has sent me as an emissary
on his behalf.
If you aid us
in our mission
I'm authorized to
increase our purchase
of tulaberry wine
to the Karemma by three percent.
Hmm, looks like a
polyduranium alloy blend.
Interesting, but the
metal has no real value.
A three percent
increase is negligible.
I have
considerable leeway
to bargain in
this circumstance.
Name your terms.
Nothing, nothing,
nothing.
The terms are
not the issue.
I cannot help you
locate the Founders
because I do not
know who they are
or if they even exist.
Nothing.
Ah, here's something
interesting.
Appears to be
diamide-laced beritium.
I'll give you
52 diraks for it.
Done.
SISKO:
Quark.
I mean, one bargain
at a time, Ornithar.
We were talking
about the Founders.
There is nothing
further to say.
If the Founders exist
they clearly do not wish
to be contacted
and that is good enough for me.
Who's your contact
in the Dominion
regarding administration,
trade, defense?
Our only contact
with the Dominion
has been through the Vorta.
I have no idea
who they report to.
All I know is that the Vorta say
to do something and you do it.
Why?
Because if you do not, they
will send in the Jem'Hadar...
and then you die.
Will you put us in contact
with the Vorta?
Commander, we do only
as we are told, nothing more.
And so far, we have not been
told to help you in any way.
You haven't been told not to,
either.
No, but I prefer to err
on the side of caution.
In this case, being cautious
will cost you
a substantial profit.
The Ferengi will cease
purchasing tulaberry
wine immediately.
If you lost such
a valuable contract
with the
Alpha Quadrant
it might displease
the Vorta.
They may even send
the Jem'Hadar
to find out
what happened.
I will need to access
one of our computers
on the surface.
( beeping )
This is the Callinon system.
The Dominion maintains
an unmanned subspace relay
on the seventh planet.
We have been told by the Vorta
to direct
all communications there.
Where the messages are sent
after that is not our concern.
What is that?
It is the Omarion Nebula.
The Omarion Nebula...
If there is nothing else,
I would like to leave now.
Of course.
Uh, Commander,
I believe
I fulfilled my role
in this mission
so if you don't mind...
You want to
stay behind?
That was our agreement.
How can you be sure
he won't turn you
over to the Dominion
as soon as we leave?
He may serve
the Dominion,
but I'm the one lining
his pockets with latinum.
I'll book passage
on the next ship going
through the wormhole
and, uh, I'll make a profit
in the process.
All right, Quark.
Good luck.
Same to you, Commander.
Lay in a course
for the Callinon system.
DAX:
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Did I wake you?
Not quite.
What can I do for you, Major?
It's about Odo.
( sighs )
You're worried about him.
Is it that obvious?
No, I'm worried about him, too.
But, at the moment, I don't know
what to do about it.
Can I speak freely?
What the hell is wrong
with Starfleet?!
How could they
do this to him?
This has been a long time
coming, Major.
Starfleet has never been
happy with the Constable.
They've been pressing me
to replace him
for the last two years.
Because he worked
for the Cardassians.
No, it goes deeper
than that.
Odo is not what you'd call
a team player.
Why? Because sometimes he
doesn't go through
the proper channels?
Well, that's a start.
You know Odo.
He enjoys thumbing his nose
at authority.
He files reports
when he feels like it.
His respect
for the chain of command
is minimal.
He gets the job done.
Starfleet likes team players.
Starfleet likes
the chain of command
and, frankly, so do I.
So you agree
with their decision?
No, but I understand it.
And when this mission is over,
you're just going to let him go?
Look, Major, I want him
to stay as much as you do,
but he has to want to stay.
T'RUL:
Bridge to Commander Sisko.
We've reached
the Callinon system.
On my way.
SISKO:
Ship's Log, supplemental.
The Defiant has cloaked
and assumed standard orbit
around Callinon VII.
I plan to send Dax and O'Brien
down to survey the relay
station on the surface.
According to our
sensor sweeps
it looks like Ornithar
was telling the truth
when he said the relay
station was unmanned.
It also appears there are very
few security measures in place.
Nothing fancy.
Get in, find what we
need and get out.
Understood.
On your way.
The transporter will need
six seconds to beam them down.
I want to de-cloak
for exactly six seconds.
Dax to Bridge.
We're ready, Benjamin.
All right.
Disengage cloak.
Energize.
They're on the surface.
Were we scanned
during transport?
I don't think so.
Dax to Defiant.
Go ahead, Dax.
We're in what seems to be
the central computer room.
The user interface
is a little unusual
but I think we
can access it.
SISKO:
Keep us posted.
I'm into the
main directory.
That was fast.
Yes, it was.
A bit too fast,
if you ask me.
Any indication
that we've tripped
some kind of
security protocol?
No, I still have
access to everything.
Then let's get
the information
and get out of here.
That's fine with me.
( gasps )
I've should have taken
Quark up on his offer
for a new replicator.
Sir?
Nothing.
Let's make good use
of this time, Major.
Begin running a level-3
diagnostic...
Dax to Defiant.
I think we have something,
Benjamin.
We've accessed
a communications log
of outgoing
transmissions.
From the way
I read this, sir
it looks like 80% of
all outgoing traffic
is sent to one location.
It's my guess it's either
another relay station
or a command center.
SISKO:
Do you have the coordinates?
I'm sending them
to you now.
( alarm blaring )
( powering down )
We've lost contact
with them.
Get them out of there!
I can't.
Some kind of shield has
appeared around the outpost.
I can't get through it.
( alarm sounding )
We're picking up three
Jem'Hadar ships, Commander
heading this way.
Can we punch
through the security shield
with our phasers
before the ships get here?
I'm not sure.
I've never seen this
kind of field before.
T'RUL:
In order to use
the phasers
we will have to de-cloak.
That means, we'll be seen
by the Jem'Hadar.
Well, we've got to do something.
We can't just leave them there.
That's exactly
what we should do, Doctor.
Leave them.
We came here to locate
the Founders.
Not to fight
the Jem'Hadar
over two expendable
crew members.
No one is expendable.
KIRA:
The Jem'Hadar have
entered the system.
They'll be in orbit
in 30 seconds.
Prepare to leave orbit, Major.
Commander...
As you were, Doctor.
Lay in a course
to the coordinates Dax sent us.
Course laid in.
Warp 7. Engage.
( sighs )
What do you think will happen
to Dax and O'Brien?
They'll probably be held
for interrogation.
If I know Dax,
she'll use the opportunity
to try to contact the Founders,
and I intend to do the same.
Sisko to Odo.
Report to the Bridge, Constable.
I want to discuss the security
arrangements for our...
ODO:
I'm presently indisposed,
Commander.
Please find someone else
for the job.
That doesn't sound like Odo.
No, it doesn't.
I'd better have a talk with him.
Uh, let me, sir.
I think he'll listen to me.
Three Jem'Hadar ships
have just entered sensor range.
Bearing 037 mark 215.
Is there any sign
they've detected us?
Negative.
Bring us out of warp
and then cut main power.
We'll wait here
until they pass.
( door chimes )
Odo, it's time
we had a talk.
I'm not going to the Bridge,
so you can save your breath.
And I'd appreciate being
left alone right now.
Well, you tried being alone
and it hasn't done any good.
So maybe it's time to stop
brooding and start talking.
Are you the ship's counselor
now?
No... I'm your friend.
You know, the one
who comes to you
when she needs help.
I'm just trying
to return the favor.
Well, you can return the favor
by giving me a shuttlecraft
and letting me go.
Go? Go where?
We're in the heart
of the Dominion.
Where the hell do you think
you're gonna go?
The Omarion Nebula.
Why?
I'm not sure why.
I just know I have to,
that's all.
Y-You... you're going to have
to do a lot better than that.
Odo...
talk to me.
Tell me what's going on.
Ever since we've come
into the Gamma Quadrant...
I've had this feeling...
of being drawn somewhere
pulled by some instinct
to a specific place--
the Omarion Nebula.
Why there?
( snorts )
I don't know.
All right.
Once we've contacted
the Founders
I'm sure Commander Sisko...
No!
Not after we've contacted
the Founders-- now!
I have to leave now!
Look, I understand
this is important to you
but we have a mission to...
( explosion )
Direct hit on the port nacelle!
How did they see through
the cloaking device?
They might have analyzed
the sensor information
on the anti-proton scan
and found a way
to penetrate the cloak.
We'll have to save
the speculation for later.
Disengage the cloak, raise the
shields and fire on my command!
Communications
and long-range sensors are out!
What's the status
of the warp drive?
The starboard power coupling
is destroyed!
I'm trying
to reroute main power!
( yelling )
He's gone!
I'll take the helm!
Locking onto the lead ship!
Ready?
Ready!
Fire!
The other two are moving
out of phaser range.
They're coming back
for another pass.
They're moving
a little slower now.
They'll be
more cautious this time.
Doctor, use
evasive pattern delta-5.
We need to keep
them off balance
until we get
warp power back.
Aye, sir.
Are you all right?
Just a few bruises.
Kira to Bridge.
Kira to Bridge!
We have to get up there.
T'Rul, where's my warp power?
I can't get the phase inducers
to align
with the ODN matrixes!
Commander, three more
Jem'Hadar warships
approaching off the port bow!
Full impulse!
Get us out of here!
We've lost main power.
We've got to get
to a shuttle.
Our duty is to get to the Bridge
and help defend the ship.
If main power is out
then the shields
are out, Kira.
The ship is
defenseless!
( grunts )
Main power is off-line!
The shields have collapsed!
I've lost helm control.
Inertial dampers failing.
Ready escape pods.
Prepare to abandon ship.
( growling )
( grunting )
( ship controls
beeping quietly )
Where am I?
You're in a shuttlecraft.
You were wounded.
Try not to move around.
Odo, what happened?
We were under attack.
The ship was boarded.
You were wounded
in the attack.
I managed to get us
to the shuttlecraft
but I don't know
much more than that.
The last time
I saw the Defiant
she was dead in space
and surrounded
by Jem'Hadar ships.
Sisko? Bashir?
I don't know.
Where are we?
We're approaching
the Omarion Nebula.
You should have taken us
back to the wormhole.
You didn't object
at the time.
I was unconscious.
You found anything?
( sighs )
That's a Class-M planet.
No star system.
A rogue planet?
Yes.
( liquid lapping )
Welcome home.