NARRATOR: Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space 9...
Our mission is to take
the Defiant
into the Gamma Quadrant
and try to find
the leaders of the
Dominion, the Founders.
What the hell is wrong
with Starfleet?
How could they
do this to him?
This has been a long time
coming, Major.
Starfleet has never been
happy with the Constable.
I want him to stay
as much as you do
but he has to want to stay.
Ever since we've come
into the Gamma Quadrant...
I've had this feeling...
of being drawn somewhere
to a specific place--
the Omarion Nebula.
( yelling )
( yells )
The last time
I saw the Defiant
she was dead in space
and surrounded
by Jem'Hadar ships.
Sisko? Bashir?
I don't know.
Welcome home.
And now the conclusion.
You really are just
like me, aren't you?
Yes.
ODO:
And you're saying,
this is where I'm from?
SHAPE-SHIFTER:
This is your home.
Ah, I wish I could
remember it.
It's understandable
that you cannot.
You were still newly formed
when you left us.
Newly formed?
You mean, I was
an infant?
An infant, yes.
Ah. I suspected
as much.
Tell me, do I have
any family at all?
Of course.
I'd like
to meet them
if that's
possible.
You already have.
We are all part
of the Great Link.
Is that all of us,
or are there others?
Odo, this isn't
a police investigation.
I'm aware of that, Major.
Well, then stop interrogating
these people.
This is the moment
you've been waiting for
all your life.
Enjoy it.
He really is
happy to be here.
Aren't you?
Yes, of course.
It's just that this
is all very sudden.
And you have many questions.
Yes.
Please...
what exactly is
this Great Link?
The Link is
the very foundation
of our society.
It provides a meaning
to our existence.
It is the merging
of form and thought
the sharing of idea
and sensation.
Is something wrong?
I've... lived
a very solitary life.
That's unfortunate,
but necessary
as you'll
learn in time.
But now, that part
of your life is over.
You're home.
What are you doing?
Take it.
But it's not time.
He isn't ready.
He's been
gone too long.
He needs
to remember
if only
for a moment.
Don't be afraid.
( deep exhale )
Odo...
What have you done to him?
I allowed him
to experience the Link.
Odo!
Yes, Major.
Are you all right?
What happened?
I'm not sure.
But I know one thing.
She's right.
I am... home.
Commander's Log, supplemental.
It's been six days since
we had to abandon the Defiant
after the Jem'Hadar attack.
We still don't know
what happened
to the rest of the crew.
Doctor Bashir and I have plotted
a course back to the wormhole.
Whether the shuttle
can get us back there or not
is questionable at best.
Our engines are failing
our external sensors
are barely functioning
and life support systems
are at 20% and dropping.
But other than that
we couldn't be
in better shape.
I thought you
were sleeping.
From the sound of things,
I wish I were.
It could be worse.
( thudding crash )
I believe you.
Do you think it's
some kind of tractor beam?
Could be.
I wish these sensors
were working.
( metallic clanging )
Now what?
Whoa, hey, don't shoot.
We surrender.
Chief, Dax.
BASHIR:
I don't believe it.
We thought you'd been
captured by the Jem'Hadar.
Well, we had our doubts
about ever seeing you again,
either, Julian.
We've been searching
for you for days.
What about the others?
No sign of them yet
but we still have ships
out looking for them.
O'BRIEN:
Meanwhile,
our orders are
to get you back to DS9
as soon as possible.
There are big things
happening there, Benjamin.
I think you're in
for a surprise.
KIRA:
This is beautiful.
( Odo sighs )
How long do they plan
on making us wait here?
We've only been here
a few hours.
Ha! I finally return home
and they still treat me
like an outsider.
Oh, believe me, you're not
the outsider here, I am.
You?
I'm the one they
don't trust, not you.
SHAPE-SHIFTER:
How perceptive, Major.
If our history
has taught us anything
it's to avoid contact
with solids whenever possible.
Solids?
Our name
for mono-forms like yourself
who will never know
the joys of the Great Link.
I don't intend to stay long.
There's a chance Sisko and
the others survived the attack.
I'm going to go back
to the shuttle
and try contacting them.
I'm sorry, I
cannot allow you
to send any communications
from the planet's surface.
They could be traced back here.
We value
our isolation.
Yes, of course.
Tell me, Odo, have you made
good use of the arboretum?
In what way?
By assuming
the various shapes
surrounding you.
Why would I do that?
To become a thing
is to know a thing.
To assume its form is to begin
to understand its existence.
Understand it?
How?
Living among the solids
has damaged you far worse
than I realized.
It has left you ignorant
of the gifts you possess.
Then teach me
what I need to know.
I'll do what I can.
But in the end,
this is another journey
you'll have
to make on your own.
And when it is over
you'll be ready
to take your place
in the Great Link.
Odo.
I'd like to be alone,
if you don't mind.
All right.
But if you need me
I'll be in the shuttle
trying to contact Sisko.
Don't worry.
When I was in the resistance,
I learned to camouflage
subspace messages
using quantum interference.
I taught the method
to Commander Sisko.
If anyone intercepts the signal,
all they'll read
is elevated levels
of background radiation.
Good luck.
You, too.
NECHAYEV:
Well, Commander,
it appears your mission
was an even greater
success than we hoped.
So I'm told.
Has the delegation
from the Founders
arrived on
the station yet?
They're already meeting
with representatives
from the Federation Council
and a dozen other
Alpha Quadrant alliances.
We're hoping to have
a treaty signed
within a matter of days
and we have you
to thank for it.
Actually, it's Lieutenant Dax
and Chief O'Brien
who deserve
most of the credit.
Well, we were lucky
the Jem'Hadar
handed us over
to the Founders.
We just had to convince them
we were serious about peace.
Actually, it didn't take
that much convincing.
I suppose
the only question is
can we trust them?
It's a risk, I know
but both the Federation Council
and Starfleet Command
believe
it's one worth taking.
By the way, Commander, one of
the Founders asked to see you
the moment you arrive
on the station.
Asked to see me?
If you're not too busy.
Well, I suppose I could
spare a few minutes.
MALE:
Commander Sisko,
come in.
I've looked forward
to meeting you.
I am Borath.
And you're one of the Founders?
That's correct.
You seem surprised.
Not really, only...
I hadn't realized till now
I've already met
one of your people.
You're referring
to Eris, of course.
Yes, she is one of us.
Though she couldn't
very well admit it
while you were pointing
a phaser at her.
( chuckles ):
I am glad to see
you're not holding one now.
Do I need one?
Oh, not at all.
You seem skeptical.
Can you blame me?
No, I realize
you have no reason
to trust the Dominion
but you must understand
that we were only trying
to defend ourselves.
From what?
We felt threatened
by your incursions
into the Gamma Quadrant.
And now?
Commander, you
risked your life
to bring us a message
of peace and friendship.
We chose to
accept your offer.
Would you have
rather we refused?
No.
Good. Because
believe me, Commander
an alliance between the Dominion
and the Federation
will be beneficial
to both our people.
Doctor, welcome back.
Why, thank you, Garak.
It's good to be back.
Yes.
Business keeping you busy?
Oh, the tailoring business
or the spy business?
I'm joking, of course.
Of course.
I've missed you.
I've been genuinely
concerned for your safety.
Lunch hasn't been
the same without you.
That's very kind of you
to say so, Garak.
Hopefully, things'll
start getting back
to normal around here.
Oh, I doubt that's going
to happen, Doctor.
I doubt that very much.
And why is that?
There's an old saying
on Cardassia:
"Enemies make
dangerous friends."
And I fear the Dominion
will make a very dangerous
friend indeed.
I take it you're referring
to the peace talks.
Exactly. I'm afraid
these treaty negotiations
are a mistake we're going
to live to regret.
Is that your opinion
or the opinion
of the Cardassian
Central Command?
The former,
I assure you.
The Central Command is very
much in favor of this treaty
which, as far as I'm concerned,
only justifies my fears.
Well, I, for one
hope you're worrying
about nothing.
Subcommander T'Rul.
You all right?
I'm fine.
I had a minor disagreement
with some Starfleet
security officers.
They refused
to allow me to speak
with the Federation's
negotiating team.
Well, what did you want
to talk to them about?
I wanted to protest
the exclusion
of the Romulan Empire
from the treaty negotiations.
I wasn't aware the Romulans
had been excluded.
Every great power in the Alpha
Quadrant has been invited
to participate
except for us.
Then there must be some mistake.
The mistake is thinking
the Romulan Empire will stand by
and allow such a betrayal
to go unchallenged.
Believe me, Doctor, if a treaty
is signed without our approval
it will mean war.
Still feel
that I'm worrying
about nothing, Doctor?
Computer, transmit
a subspace signal
using a narrow
theta band frequency
shifted into
a background radiation domain.
COMPUTER:
Working.
I hope you're out there,
Commander.
Unable to transmit signal
due to external interference
at all frequencies.
Identify source of interference.
Interference generated
by thermal radiation
from a subterranean
power source.
Locate power source.
Power source is located
four kilometers
beneath the planet's surface.
Coordinates 127 mark 3.
Can you identify?
Unable to identify due to an
unknown poly-metallic substance
within the surrounding rock.
Any luck, Major?
No, some kind
of power source
is interfering
with my signal.
Do you have any idea
what it could be?
I haven't a clue.
Are you all right?
( sighs )
I have spent the last two hours
shape-shifting--
rocks, flowers, trees--
I have been everything
in that... garden.
And?
And nothing.
Oh, I can become
a rock all right
but I have no more of an idea
what it is to be a rock
than I did before.
I'm not really sure
what that means.
I'm not sure either
and that's... unfortunate.
( sighs )
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to return to my bucket.
DAX:
Commander, Admiral Nechayev
is here to see you.
Send her in.
( door opens )
NECHAYEV:
You asked to see
me, Commander?
I understand
that the Romulans
haven't been invited
to the peace talks.
That's correct.
I was wondering
what prompted that decision.
The Founders requested
that they be excluded.
Did they say why?
They felt the Romulans
would be
a disruptive influence.
More disruptive
than the Cardassians?
They seemed to think so.
Do you have a problem
with this, Commander?
Whether I have a problem with it
isn't the point.
It's the Romulans
we have to worry about.
Commander, if this treaty
is signed,
and I'm confident it will be,
we'll never have to worry
about the Romulans again.
Are you sure of that?
Quite sure.
After all, what chance
would they have
against the combined power
of our new alliance?
They wouldn't have
much of a chance at all.
I'm glad we agree.
Believe me, Commander
the Federation carefully
weighed all the options
before entering
into these peace talks.
I realize that.
Then we have nothing
further to discuss, do we?
Why do you dislike
humanoids so much?
I know they
have their flaws
but I've found many of them
to be kind, decent people.
Like Major Kira?
Yes, like Major Kira.
Then you've been more fortunate
than most changelings.
"Changelings?"
You recognize the term?
Hmm. I've been called
a "changeling" on occasion.
It's a name given
to us by the solids.
They meant it as an insult
but, in defiance,
we took it and made it our own.
Go on, please.
The Great Link tells us
that many years ago
our people
roamed the stars
searching out other races,
so we could add
to our knowledge
of the galaxy.
We went in peace,
but too often we were met
with suspicion,
hatred and violence.
Why?
The solids feared our
metamorphic abilities.
So we were beaten,
hunted and killed.
Finally, we arrived here.
And here
safe in our isolation,
we made our home.
Tell me... why was I sent away?
Because even in our isolation
we desired to learn
more about the galaxy.
You were one of
100 infants sent off
to gain that
knowledge for us.
But how could you be sure
that we'd find
our way back here?
You had no choice.
The urge to return home
was implanted
in your genetic makeup.
And now, thanks
to the passageway
you're the first one
to return to us.
We weren't expecting you
so soon.
When were you expecting me?
Not for another 300 years.
How long was I away?
A long time.
But now, all that matters
is that you're here.
It's...
different than I
imagined it would be.
Whatever you imagined,
I promise it will be better.
Odo, are you here?
Odo...
I'm going to try to track
the source of the interference.
If I can't find it
and neutralize it
I'm going to have to leave here
and try to find
Sisko and the others.
( sighs )
I'm really glad
you made it home, Odo.
I know everything is going
to work out just fine.
I don't believe it.
I'm talking to a tree.
You're probably not
even here, are you?
Why would shape-shifters
need a door?
Kira to computer.
Scan the area dead ahead of me
for 100 meters.
Unable to penetrate
due to interference.
QUARK:
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
After you.
Look out.
Coming through.
Sorry to keep you
waiting, gentlemen.
That's two synthales,
on the house.
What's put you
in such a good humor?
I have inside information
that the peace agreement
is about to be finalized.
And where did you get
this information?
From one of your friends
on the Federation Council?
If you must know, I overheard
two Jem'Hadar officers.
And you
believed them?
I don't see why not.
Oh, I know we got off
to a rocky start
but they're not so bad.
Really.
I think they have the gene.
What gene?
The gambling gene.
They've barely been
on this station a week
and already they can hardly
drag themselves away
from the dabo table.
How fortunate for you.
How fortunate
for all of us.
You see, I have a dream...
a dream that one day
all people--
human, Jem'Hadar, Ferengi
Cardassians--
will stand together in peace...
around my dabo tables.
You're a regular
visionary, Quark.
I am, aren't I?
You're in my way!
Sorry.
( grunts )
Now, look!
( crowd gasps,
glass shatters )
Gentlemen, please,
remember my vision.
That's enough.
All right.
What's going on here?
He addressed me in
a disrespectful tone.
That's a lie.
Easy, Doctor.
We're all friends here.
Tell him that.
I'll see this
doesn't happen again.
I expect you will.
Is that it?
You're just going to
let him walk away?
Our orders are to give
the Jem'Hadar a wide berth.
Look, I know what
the orders say
but he attacked
Chief O'Brien,
and we have rules here
against that sort of thing.
I'm aware of station
regulations, Doctor.
However,
the Jem'Hadar are not.
We have to allow them
some time to get used
to our customs.
So, in the meantime
they're free to do
whatever they want.
Remember that
before you get into
another brawl with them.
JAKE:
Dad, pass me
the potatoes.
Dad?
Yes, Jake.
The potatoes.
Oh.
Dad, is something wrong?
( sighs )
Not really.
I'm just a little preoccupied,
that's all.
It's these Dominion
negotiations.
What about them?
Well, it's
all happening
behind closed doors.
I... I guess I just feel...
out of the loop.
There's something going on,
isn't there?
Like what?
You tell me.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Benjamin.
Did you know about this?
Know about what?
I being transferred
to the Lexington.
I'm their new
Science Officer.
There must be
some mistake.
The orders are
right here.
Let me see this.
I don't believe it.
Bashir to Sisko.
Go ahead, Doctor.
Commander, I need to talk
to you about the Jem'Hadar.
I want to know
what the hell is going on!
Commander, I don't appreciate
your barging in here.
I want to know
why my Science Officer's
been transferred
without my consent.
I want to know
why my Chief of Operations
is lying in the Infirmary
while the Jem'Hadar who beat him
is free to walk the station.
And I want to know
why the Federation is willing
to risk a war with the Romulans
to form an alliance
with a group of people that we
hardly know and barely trust!
Are you finished?
I haven't even begun!
BORATH:
Admiral, I think you
should tell Commander Sisko
what he wants to know.
All right, I
suppose he deserves
to be the first
to hear the news.
What news?
The Federation is pulling
out of this sector.
All Starfleet
personnel currently
stationed on DS9
will be reassigned
to other posts.
Yourself included.
What about Bajor?
Our plans for Bajor
are on hold for the time being.
From now on, Bajor will be
the Dominion's responsibility.
They'll be running
this station.
And you're telling me that the
Bajorans have agreed to this?
We're confident
they'll have no objections.
And if they do object,
what then?
You send in the Jem'Hadar?
BORATH:
The Jem'Hadar
are used
only against
our enemies.
Bajor will be protected,
Commander.
We'll see to it.
What about the wormhole?
Will they get
to protect that, too?
It's the price of peace,
Benjamin.
Well, if you ask me,
the price is too damned high.
What is the Federation supposed
to get out of all of this?
Our friendship.
Isn't that enough?
NECHAYEV:
And you, Benjamin,
get a promotion...
Captain Sisko.
It's an important step
toward that Admiralcy
you've always wanted.
I want a chance to speak to
the Federation negotiating team
before this treaty is signed!
It's too late for that, Ben.
The treaty was signed
late this afternoon.
( sighs in frustration )
( pounds table )
It's the beginning
of a new era, Commander
and you helped
make it possible.
Congratulations.
( squawks )
Odo.
I've been
waiting for you.
Major!
I have just had the most
remarkable experience.
For a few moments
I actually felt
what it was like
to be an Arbazon vulture.
The air currents
beneath my wings
the exhilaration of soaring
above the treetops.
Oh, it was all...
very stimulating.
I'm so happy for you.
I know you are.
So, I guess this means
you'll be staying
here a while.
I've enjoyed working
with you, Major.
with you, too, Odo.
But, before
we say good-bye
I need your help
one last time.
Certainly.
Remember that
power source
I was telling you about?
The one preventing you
from trying to contact
Commander Sisko.
Well, I found it.
And what did it turn out to be?
I couldn't tell.
There was a door
blocking my path.
I need you to help me open it.
What kind of door?
It's composed
of some kind metal
that the tricorder
couldn't identify.
Other than that, it,
it's an ordinary door.
That's odd.
My people have
no need for doors.
They dislike taking
humanoid form.
I know.
Then who could be using it?
Ah, Commander.
I was hoping to see
you before you left.
I just wanted
to tell you
how impressed
I've been with you
during these
past two years.
You've run this station
with strength, dignity
and compassion.
Well done.
Thank you, Mr. Garak.
But I'm sure you'll
be back before long.
Though from
what I've heard
it'll be to fight
against Bajor.
I've heard
the same rumors.
That Bajor has forged
a pact with the Romulans
to stand against
the Jem'Hadar...
and their allies.
Oh, the Bajorans have fought
for their freedom before.
It only makes sense that
they'd fight for it again.
So much for
my peace mission.
Do I detect
a note
of bitterness in your voice?
I wouldn't be surprised.
If it means anything to you,
Commander
I happen to share your feelings
about this Dominion treaty.
I've thought about it
a great deal
and the only explanation
I can find
is that our leaders
have simply gone insane.
It seems that way.
Unfortunately, there's nothing
you or I can do about it.
I suppose not.
After all,
you have
your orders, and as for me,
well...
( chuckles )
I wouldn't dream
of opposing the wishes
of the Central Command.
Pity.
I agree...
that it's a pity.
I thought you would.
Mr. Garak, I never knew
we thought so much alike.
Life is full of surprises,
Commander.
Hmm.
T'RUL:
Commander Sisko!
Ah! There she is!
No!
( groaning )
EDDINGTON:
Can I help you?
We're here to see
Commander Sisko.
Sorry, my orders are
no one sees him.
But we're here
on urgent business.
Well, you'll have to talk
to Admiral Nechayev.
She's in charge here
until the Jem'Hadar...
I'm afraid you have
a loose thread
right here.
I'm sorry
but we are pressed for time.
I'll get Sisko.
Doctor, if you'd be so kind
as to take his legs.
If I didn't know better
I'd say you were
enjoying yourself, Garak.
Oh, not at all, Doctor
but after years
of hemming women's dresses
a little action is
a welcome change of pace.
I hope you feel the same
way an hour from now.
The first thing
we need to do is
to get our hands
on a runabout.
It's already taken
care of, Benjamin.
The Chief's waiting for us
at Landing Pad C
with the Rio Grande
and a full complement
of photon torpedoes.
How did you know we needed
photon torpedoes?
I know you.
You want to make sure
the Dominion
stays on their side
of the galaxy,
and the only way
to do that
is to collapse the entrance
to the wormhole.
I'm glad we're
all in agreement.
Well, I guess this means
the end
of our Starfleet careers.
Oh, I wouldn't worry
about that, Doctor.
Well, that's easy
for you to say.
Oh, you misunderstand
me, Lieutenant.
All I meant was
it's a little foolish
to worry about your careers
at a time like this,
when there's a good chance
we're all about to be killed.
Interesting.
Judging by this
locking mechanism
the purpose of this door
is not to keep people out
but rather to keep
whatever's on
the other side in.
Do you think you
can get it open?
We'll see.
Halt!
Put down
your weapons.
I have them,
I have them.
By all means,
Commander
do as they say.
Garak.
Now you heard
me, Doctor.
Well, I'm glad to see
the plan is going
as scheduled.
What plan is that?
You mean no one told you?
You see, I pretend
to be their friend
and then I shoot you.
Well done, Garak.
Well, it's just something
I read once in a book.
I'm sure.
( groaning )
Garak!
Garak.
Doctor, I'm afraid
I won't be able
to have lunch
with you today.
We've got to go.
Come on.
Move it, Lieutenant.
I'm right behind you.
Get us out of here, Chief.
What about Garak?
He's not coming.
I see.
Hang on.
We'll reach the wormhole
in 30 seconds.
Prepare to launch
photon torpedoes.
We're being hailed.
It's Admiral Nechayev.
Commander, I'm ordering you
to stand down.
Return to the station
immediately.
I'm afraid I'm going to have
to refuse that order.
Please, Commander
don't make us send
the Jem'Hadar after you.
Go right ahead,
but you better warn them
not to expect any reinforcements
for about 70 years.
Attack pattern theta,
Mr. O'Brien. Hard a-port.
Yes, sir.
( whirring clicks )
( lock disengaging )
Step back, Major.
Please, come in.
Commander.
They can't hear you.
What have you
done to them?
Nothing harmful.
We're just conducting
a little experiment.
What kind of experiment?
To see how they'd respond
to an attempt by the Dominion
to gain a foothold
into the Alpha Quadrant.
We were curious to see
how much they'd be
willing to sacrifice
in order to avoid a war.
And what have you found out?
Unfortunately...
( chuckles )
...they're proving to be
just as stubborn as I'd feared.
I'm glad to hear it.
You are?
Well, that is a problem.
But thankfully,
it's not one I  have to solve.
SHAPE-SHIFTER:
But I do.
I don't understand.
You knew about this?
Yes.
But how could
you allow it?
You belong to the
Dominion, don't you?
Belong to it?
Major, the changelings
are the Dominion.
You're the Founders.
Ironic, isn't it?
The hunted now control
the destinies
of hundreds of other races.
But...
why control anyone?
Because what you can control
can't hurt you.
So, many years ago,
we set ourselves the task
of imposing order
on a chaotic universe.
Is that what you call it?
Imposing order?
I call it murder.
What you call it is
no concern of ours.
How do you justify
the deaths of so many people?
The solids have always
been a threat to us--
that's the only
justification we need.
Well, these solids
have never harmed you.
They travel the galaxy in order
to expand their knowledge
just as you once did.
The solids are nothing like us.
No... I suppose they're not.
And neither am I.
I've devoted my life
to the pursuit of justice,
but justice means nothing
to you, does it?
It is not justice
you desire, Odo
but order, the same as we do.
And we can help you
satisfy that desire
in ways the solids never could.
This will all
become clear to you
once you've taken your place
in the Great Link.
No.
I admit this...
Link of yours is appealing,
but you see, I already
have a link...
with these people.
I want you to remove
those devices
and bring them
their combadges.
We can't allow
them to leave.
And I can't allow you
to keep them here.
They're leaving.
And so am I.
It's taken you many years
to find your way back home.
Are you really willing
to leave it again so soon?
Unless you intend to stop me.
No changeling has
ever harmed another.
Whatever you do to them
you're going
to have to do to me.
They are free to go.
Thank you.
The next time, I promise you,
we will not be so generous.
Major... Constable.
What happened to
the Rio Grande?
DAX:
The last thing I remember
is collapsing the wormhole.
T'RUL:
The last thing I remember
is being shot
by some Jem'Hadar soldier.
I'm sure it all
seemed very real
but the truth is you've
been held in this room
since the Jem'Hadar brought
you here from the Defiant.
Borath, what the hell
is going on here?
Your ship is in orbit.
You may transport back to it
whenever you're ready.
ODO:
Commander, I'll
be along shortly.
I'll stay down here
and make sure
that he gets back
to the ship.
Another shape-shifter.
Commander, you must leave now.
I give you my word I'll
explain everything later.
I'll look forward to it.
Sisko to Defiant.
Five to beam up.
I hope that one day
you'll return to us, Odo
and take your rightful place
within the Dominion.
I don't think
that's possible.
Your link to the solids
won't last.
You will always
be an outsider.
Being an outsider
isn't so bad.
It gives one
a unique perspective.
It's a pity
you've forgotten that.
Then perhaps one day,
I'll come visit you.
The Alpha Quadrant seems
wracked with chaos.
It could use some order.
Imposing your type of order
on the Alpha Quadrant
may prove more difficult
than you imagine.
We are willing to wait
until the time is right.
We will miss you, Odo,
but you will miss us even more.
Odo?
Ready, Major.
Kira to Defiant.
Two to beam up.