How's it going, Jake?
Fine. I've deleted
half the Cardassian files
from the computer.
I can't believe how many
subroutines it took
just to run
this ore processor.
Well, it used to be
a pretty large operation.
When the Cardassians
were in charge
I understand they processed
20,000 tons a day.
That's a lot of ore.
It must've been
hell in here.
I heard stories
the temperature
reached 55 degrees Celsius.
How could the Bajoran
workers survive that?
Oh, a lot of them didn't.
When you've deleted
all those files,
I'll show you how to download
the new operating system.
You really think
we can convert this place
into a deuterium refinery?
Absolutely.
It'll take
us three...
maybe four
weeks at most.
I hope you're
planning on eating
during the next
three or four weeks.
Commander, I guess
I lost track
of the time.
JAKE:
We're almost
finished, Dad.
Chief, I'm having a problem
deleting one of these files.
Have you tried reformatting
the data cluster?
Yeah, but the file's
still here.
Here, let me see.
Well, that's odd.
What's that, Chief?
Well, the file has no name,
no indication what it is.
I better set it
aside for now.
I can transfer it to the
central database in Ops,
and analyze it
in the morning.
( console beeping )
Wait a minute.
COMPUTER:
Unauthorized computer entry
detected
in Ore Processing Unit 5.
Enter access code.
( keyboard beeping )
Incorrect code.
You have five seconds
to enter correct access code.
Or what?
I don't know,
but I better stop it.
( alarm sounding )
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Worker revolt in progress
in Ore Processing Unit 5.
Security countermeasures
initiated.
What the hell?
Bajoran workers,
your attention, please.
Your attempt to seize
control of this facility
is going to fail.
You are valuable workers,
and we wish you no harm.
However, if you do not
return control of this unit
to your Cardassian
supervisors,
we will be forced
to take action.
You have eight minutes
to make your decision.
The computer's engaged
the magnetic seal.
I can't override it.
KIRA:
Ops to Sisko.
Go ahead.
Commander, what is
going on down there?
We just got a recorded message
from Gul Dukat
regarding some worker revolt
in the ore processing facility?
We saw the same message.
It seems we've tripped
some kind of automated security
program the Cardassians left.
We're locked in.
Oh, we'll beam you
out of there.
COMPUTER:
Enter access code.
What?
If this security program
thinks there's been
some kind of worker's revolt,
then it must think
this station is still
under Cardassian rule.
So it's probably waiting for us
to enter an emergency code.
One that the Cardassians
never bothered to give us
when they left.
Odo to Ops.
Kira here.
My Cardassian access codes
are still valid.
I'm attempting to override
the security program,
but it's going
to take some time.
I'm not sure my clearance level
is high enough.
KIRA:
Well, keep at it.
We'll try to do the same thing
from up here.
Acknowledged.
Odo, do you
mind telling me
what this is all about?
That message from
Dukat is making my
customers nervous.
And when they're nervous,
they're not...
Not now, Quark.
I'm busy.
Well, is there anything
I can do to help?
Not unless you have
a level 9 Cardassian
security clearance.
Let's see.
I think I have everything
from levels 1 through 7.
I only have
levels 1 through 6.
Well.
If you'd like a level 7
I'm sure we can make
some kind of arrangement.
Leave me alone, Quark.
Oh, no.
There's something
very wrong going on,
and this is the safest place
in the whole station.
I think I'll stay right here.
Any luck?
Nothing.
It's probably magnetically
sealed, like the door.
We'd need a phaser
to blast it open.
Well, there's no way
I can disable
the program from here.
DUKAT:
Bajoran workers,
your time is running out,
but it's not too late.
You can still surrender
and save your lives.
Computer, this is the leader
of the Bajoran workers.
We surrender.
DUKAT:
I'm glad to see
you've come to your senses.
Stay where you are.
When Cardassian Security
arrives,
they will place you
into custody,
but you will not be harmed.
You have my word.
For whatever that's worth.
Now what?
SISKO:
Well, it sounds like
the program is going to wait
for Cardassian security
to enter the
all-clear protocol.
That'll give us
a few minutes anyway.
What's in here?
Nothing at
the moment.
Processed uridium used
to pour down that pipe
to a secondary
refining facility
in Level 33
and be purified.
It's not locked.
Since that pipe was filled
with molten uridium,
there wasn't any need
for security measures.
Well, it's too narrow
for anyone to escape through.
I can get in there.
Chief, if he can crawl
up this pipe into the machine,
can he get
to the ore chute
and open that hatch
from inside?
DUKAT:
Bajoran workers,
you have not surrendered
to Cardassian security.
If you do not do so
in the next three minutes,
I will be forced
to release neurocine gas
into the ore processing
facility.
I can do it.
DUKAT:
Bajoran workers,
you have two minutes left
to give yourselves up
to your Cardassian overseers
and save your lives.
Can you hear me, Jake?
JAKE:
Loud and clear,
but I can't see a thing.
There should be a large circular
opening to your right.
JAKE:
Okay, let me see
if I can find it.
DUKAT:
Even if you were
to escape this station...
( metallic thud )
JAKE:
Ow!
SISKO:
Jake-o, you all right?
JAKE:
Yeah, I just banged
my head on something.
DUKAT:
...back to Bajor?
JAKE:
Wait a second.
There's a junction here.
It feels like it goes
off in two directions.
Which way do I go?
Follow this
sound, Jake.
( banging )
JAKE:
Do it again, Dad.
( banging )
JAKE:
Got it.
I'm in the chute.
There should be
a small access port
on one of the walls.
JAKE:
Found it.
Open the hatch
and feel around inside
for a handle.
It should be shaped
like a stirrup.
( Dukat continues speaking )
You know, I never knew
how much this man's
voice annoyed me.
JAKE:
I can reach it,
but I can't get a hold of it.
You have to pull
the handle down, Jake.
It's the release
for the hatch.
JAKE:
I'm trying! I can't...
SISKO:
Don't tense up.
Relax.
Now just take a deep
breath and try again.
I'm sorry,
but your time has run out.
I was hoping
you would be reasonable.
Rest assured that your deaths
will serve as an example
to prevent similar
incidents in the future.
I got it!
Dax!
Maybe if we bypass
the primary command pathway
and cross-connect
the backup with the ODN.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Workers have escaped
from Ore Processing Unit 5.
Initiating station-wide
counterinsurgency program.
( alarm blares )
Now what?
DUKAT:
Attention, Bajoran workers.
I will not allow
this rebellion to succeed.
If you do not
surrender immediately,
I will be forced to kill
every Bajoran on this station.
( grunting and scuffling )
Wait a second.
I found something.
SISKO:
What is it?
I don't know.
Some kind of room.
It sure is dirty.
Doesn't smell too good either.
SISKO:
Looks like some
kind of loading bay.
You're right.
This is where
the uridium ore
was separated
from the rock.
Then it would be
dumped down that chute
to the processing
facility.
( banging )
Locked.
Chief, is there
another way out of here?
Just back down
that chute.
You know where
that leads to.
Sisko to Ops.
Sisko to Security.
Try yours.
O'Brien to Ops.
Jake Sisko to anyone
who can hear me.
Something must
be interfering
with the signal.
What do we do now?
It's no good.
We're completely cut off
from the rest of the station.
BASHIR:
There must be some kind
of general dampening field
in place.
It must be disrupting
communications.
All right.
It's time for a less
subtle approach.
Doctor.
Ah, the Cardassians don't
miss a trick, do they?
DAX:
The ironic thing is
that field is probably there
to protect Ops
from the hordes
of rebelling Bajorans.
KIRA:
Well, we've got
to find a way
of disabling
the security program
or a lot of people
are going to get killed.
If we can regain
control of the main computer,
we may be able to wipe
the security program
from its memory.
Now, if I can reroute
the APT relay
through the secondary buffer,
I might get an independent
terminal working.
You know, I've been here
nearly three years,
and I was just finally
starting to think
of this place as home.
Your "home" was built
by Cardassians, Doctor.
Don't ever forget that.
Well, there's not much chance
of that, is there?
What do you mean,
we're trapped?
I mean, we're trapped.
I wouldn't be surprised
if the entire station
is locked down.
QUARK:
But you're
a shape-shifter.
Excuse me, a changeling.
So change into something
and get us out of here.
This force field isn't
just protecting the door.
It goes through the bulkheads,
the ceiling, the deck.
There's nowhere
for me to go.
You're telling me
I'm stuck here...
with you?
No...
I'm stuck here with you.
Believe me, a far worse fate.
( keyboard beeping )
And stay away from my computer!
( grunting )
Again!
Oh, okay. Hold on.
JAKE:
Anything?
Not even a dent.
There has to be something
else we can do.
What about
all this ore?
As I understand it,
uridium is very unstable.
That's true,
but in its raw form,
you need a strong electrical
charge to detonate it.
Can we use that?
Well, if I had some tools,
I might be able to get in there
and yank out
some electrical cable.
Tools.
How's it coming?
DAX:
Almost done.
( electrical hissing,
Dax yells )
Jadzia!
Get me a medkit.
Easy, Jadzia.
I have to take a look.
I was reaching toward
the ODN conduit,
and a small force
field went off,
and it caught my hands.
Well, they're
second-degree burns,
but I don't think
there's any neural damage.
This should
relieve the pain.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Security
in the Operations Center
has been compromised.
Initiating counterinsurgency
program level two.
DUKAT:
Attention, Bajoran workers.
Your failure to surrender
is forcing me
to take stronger measures.
In five minutes, we will
begin pumping neurocine gas
into the Habitat Ring.
Think of your families
as you consider
your course of action.
All Cardassian personnel should
evacuate the area immediately.
Habitat Ring. There have
to be hundreds of people
trapped in their quarters
out there.
GARAK:
I believe that's
the point, Major.
Computer,
access code: Garak 1359.
Ironic, isn't it?
The only place
in the galaxy that still
recognizes my access code
is a Bajoran
space station.
If you can get past
the force fields,
you've got to get out
to the Habitat Ring
and start evacuating
those people before...
I'd like nothing better
than to help my loyal customers,
but it's not that simple.
My access code enables me
to move about the station,
but unfortunately,
as you've just seen,
the force fields reappear
the moment I pass
through a doorway.
Have you tried
using your code
to shut down the
security program?
Several times, but for some
reason I can't begin to fathom,
Gul Dukat
chose not to trust me
with his top-level security
codes during the occupation.
Garak, do you know a way
we can stop this neurocine gas?
The only way
to do that
is to destroy
the life support system.
What are you trying to do,
Garak, get us all killed?
No, wait a minute.
He's right.
The neurocine gas
is released through
the life support systems.
Destroy it and we save everybody
in the Habitat Ring.
For 12 hours,
and then everyone
on the station
will suffocate when
we run out of oxygen.
Well, that gives us 12 hours
to regain control
of this station.
Believe me, Major,
it's the only way
to save those people.
I believe life support is
controlled from over there.
Get down.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Counterinsurgency
program level two
has been interrupted.
Initiating counterinsurgency
program level three.
DUKAT:
My fellow Cardassians,
I regret to inform you
that Bajoran workers
have gained control
of this station.
In all likelihood, I am dead
or otherwise incapacitated.
But rest assured,
this station will not be allowed
to remain in Bajoran hands.
However, it is
my duty to inform you
that if you do not regain
control within two hours,
the station will be destroyed.
COMPUTER:
Self-destruct sequence
initiated.
Come on.
Come on!
Give me that before
you hurt yourself.
( sighs )
I've checked the entire
security complex.
There's no way out.
I should've listened
to my father.
He always warned me
this was going to happen.
What? That you'd spend
your final hours in jail?
I could've told you that.
No.
He warned me
never to leave home.
He said there were plenty
of business opportunities
right outside my door.
But, no, I had to follow
the 75th Rule of Acquisition:
"Home is where the heart is, but
the stars are made of latinum."
A lifetime of scheming
and plotting,
wheeling and dealing,
and what has it got me?
One measly little bar.
My Uncle Frin owns 30.
And my Cousin Gaila...
I know-- he
owns a moon.
I told you that?
Many times.
It's a small moon,
but it's enough to live on.
Oh, come on, Quark.
You've done all
right for yourself.
Oh, what do you know?
Quark, I've met a lot
of Ferengis in my time,
and the truth is,
though some of them may
have been more wealthy,
I've never met
one more devious.
Really?
Would I lie?
I guess not.
Thank you, Odo.
That means a lot to me.
Now...
can I have the phaser back?
No.
( angry yell )
( frustrated sigh )
How do your hands feel?
A little better.
Good. I wish I could
have done more,
but I won't be able to
repair the damaged tissue
until we can get you
to the Infirmary.
Any luck?
Plenty, Major.
Unfortunately,
all of it bad.
My personal code can
activate any terminal
on this station.
However, that's the
extent of my access.
All I can do is
just look around.
I can tell you exactly
what's going on,
but I can't do
anything about it.
As far as I can see,
the only person
who can disable the security
program is Gul Dukat.
Maybe there's a way
to fool the computer
into thinking
that you are Gul Dukat.
You could try rewriting
your code to match his.
Even if I could,
it wouldn't do any good.
If I were to input his code,
the computer would scan
my DNA pattern
to determine
if I really were Dukat.
DAX:
But what if
we disable
the sensors in Ops
so that the computer
couldn't scan you?
What a creative idea.
It certainly is
worth a try.
The question is,
can we disconnect the sensors
without anyone else
getting hurt?
We're just going
to have to take that chance.
DAX:
We could switch
the sensor input
from the primary scanners
to the backup scanners.
The computer
shouldn't see that
as a threat
but it'll blind
the system for a few seconds
while we make the changeover.
If it works, a few seconds
are all I'll need.
Major, I'm going to need a hand.
Well, tell me, Doctor,
what is it exactly
about this situation
that's making you smile?
You, Garak.
Hmm?
Just wondering how
many other tailors
can rewrite Cardassian
security protocols.
I wouldn't even
venture a guess.
Which reminds me,
those pants
you wanted altered
are ready to be picked up.
Oh, this is a problem.
What's wrong?
I always suspected that Dukat
was a little paranoid.
He's left a rather large number
of interrogative subroutines
imbedded in his access code.
Meaning what?
Meaning the computer is
constantly challenging me
to prove that I am
who I say I am.
Lieutenant,
how much longer before you can
disable those sensors?
Oh, at least
another ten minutes.
I'm not sure
we have that much time.
In fact,
I'm sure we don't.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Unauthorized use
of command code.
Initiating counterinsurgency
program level four.
( groaning )
On three.
One, two,
three.
You did it.
Okay, we have
the power cable.
Now, we need to pack
the uridium
around the door.
My phaser's on the Ops table!
Can anyone get to it?
The answer, Major, is no.
Well, we can't stay here
and do nothing.
I respectfully disagree, Major.
Nothing is about all we can do.
Let me guess.
Someone tried
to duplicate
my access code, hmm?
Dukat!
What the hell are
you doing here?!
A short time ago, I had
a very strange experience.
There I was, patrolling
the Demilitarized Zone
when I received
a distress signal... from me,
or at least
a recording of me.
It seems the Bajoran workers
were rioting on Terok Nor.
( laughs )
I must admit,
it piqued my curiosity.
I see.
The autodestruct program
has begun.
Well, well,
well...
you are in trouble.
Where's Commander Sisko?
I trust he wasn't vaporized
while asking for one of those
raktajinos he's so fond of.
No, last we heard,
he was trapped
in the ore processing unit.
Hmm.
I wish him well.
Well, can you help us or not?
Oh, most certainly.
All I have to do is
enter my command code
and shut down the program.
Well, then do it!
All in good time, Major Kira.
All in good time.
But, first, there are a few
things we should discuss.
Red leaf tea, please.
Doctor.
What do you want, Dukat?
You'll find I don't react well
to that tone of voice, Major.
( laughs )
Garak, groveling
in a corner.
That alone makes
my trip worthwhile.
Garak!
Easy, Doctor.
It would appear
that the computer is
only targeting non-Cardassians.
If you had been on the station
when I designed this program,
I would have made an exception
in your case.
Well, you've always
been shortsighted.
It's held you back
over the years.
As I recall, your father
had the same flaw.
My father's only flaw
was trusting you.
Funny, at his trial,
your father said
that his biggest flaw was
that his ambition outweighed
his patriotism.
Maybe you two could settle
this at another time!
You're right, Major.
But believe me, Garak,
that time is coming.
Major!
Why don't you join me
in the Commander's office
where we can talk in private?
Oh! I forgot.
The replicator.
Well, it's the least I can do.
You can all rise now.
You're safe.
For the moment.
Major.
( sighs )
I know time is of
the essence, Major...
so I'll be brief.
I think it is time
to reestablish a permanent
Cardassian presence
aboard
this station.
Nothing too
elaborate,
mind you.
A garrison would suffice.
I can deploy troops
from my ship immediately.
And in return, I'll solve
your current dilemma.
Well, you know I'm never going
to agree to that.
I'm not sure you have
much of a choice here.
Dukat, you and I both know
neither Bajor nor the Federation
will ever honor an agreement
negotiated under
a death threat.
( laughs )
I don't expect them
to be happy about it.
But once my troops
are in place,
I think you'll find it very
difficult to get them to leave.
Well, let me put
this another way.
I will destroy this station
before I ever give it back
to the Cardassians.
Yes... I'm sure you would.
But...
would you allow 2,000
people aboard this station
to die simply because
you don't like... us?
Hmm.
Well...
there's no need
to decide just yet.
We still have
a little time left.
30 minutes, in fact.
Why don't I
return to my ship
so that you'll have time
to think about it?
Hmm?
I'll be back...
in, say, 25 minutes.
Dukat. One
to transport.
Energize.
CARDASSIAN:
Dukat, if you are seeing
this recording,
it means you tried
to abandon your post
while the station's
self- destruct sequence
was engaged.
That will not be permitted.
This is outrageous!
You have lost control of Terok
Nor, disgracing yourself
and Cardassia.
Your attempt
to escape is no doubt
a final act of cowardice.
All fail-safes
have been eliminated.
Your personal access codes
have been rescinded.
The destruct sequence
can no longer be halted.
All you can do now
is contemplate
the depth of your disgrace,
and try to die
like a Cardassian.
DUKAT:
Computer, abort
the self-destruct sequence.
This is a priority one override,
clearance level 9.
Authorization:
Dukat 5116 green.
COMPUTER:
Request denied.
All authorization codes
are void.
Time to self-destruct:
25 minutes.
( laughs )
Even your own computer
program turns against you.
I always knew
your shortsightedness
would be your downfall.
I don't see you coming up
with any ideas, tailor.
Look, if you two are
finished with the insults,
we could use some help here.
Now, what can you tell us about
the self-destruct sequence?
It's very simple.
When the countdown
is completed,
the computer will order
the main fusion reactor
to disengage the
reaction stabilizers,
causing it to overload,
destroying the station.
What about the reactor?
Is there any way
to shut it down?
It may be possible
to manually disengage
the laser fusion initiator,
but in order to do that,
we have to be
in the reactor room.
DAX:
Not necessarily.
We can disengage the initiator
from one of the control
junctions on level 34.
But now the computer's
wiped out the access codes,
not even a Cardassian
can get out of this room.
Well, then maybe
we should concentrate
on trying to eliminate the force
field protecting the door.
We don't have time
to eliminate
every force field
between here and level 34.
What we need to do
is find a way to deactivate
all the force fields
on the station at the same time.
Okay, that should do it.
If we use much more,
we run the risk
of bringing the whole room
down around our ears.
SISKO:
All right, we'd
better take cover.
Would you... like
to do the honors, sir?
Keep your heads down.
JAKE:
It worked!
I set up this program,
and I assure you, Major,
I will find a way
to defeat it.
There is no dilemma
that cannot be solved
by a disciplined
Cardassian mind.
It's not going
to work, you know.
What are you
babbling on about now?
I'm talking about Major Kira.
What about her?
She's much too busy
trying to save this station
to be impressed
with your incessant posturing.
Garak!
And even
if she weren't,
she has much better taste
than to be attracted to you.
You, a married man.
I should have executed you
years ago.
Oh, you tried, remember?
BASHIR:
Garak.
This isn't helping.
Wait a minute.
What about the
power supply grid?
If we could overload
the grid, we might be able
to cause a power surge
and short out
all the force fields
on the station.
KIRA:
It might
even be enough
to eliminate
the dampening field
that's been keeping us
from using our communicators.
Tell me something, Major.
The Cardassian
neutralization emitters
that were under here--
I assume you
deactivated them
when you took control
of this station?
That's right.
We prefer our
containment fields
to be nonlethal.
But are the emitters
still in place?
As far as I know.
Excellent!
That means that they
have not been affected
by the counterinsurgency
program.
That means, we still
have control of them.
DAX:
Then, if we can get
the emitters
back on line,
we can use them
to overload
the power grid.
Exactly.
Do you think it'll be enough
to eliminate the force fields?
Unfortunately, we'll lose
the turbolifts
and the transporters
but they aren't much use
to us right now anyway.
Let's give it a try.
SISKO:
Anything?
I only got a couple
a hundred meters
and I was stopped
by a force field.
How about you?
JAKE:
We didn't even
get that far.
There's got to be
some way up to Ops.
The turbolift shaft!
We can climb it
all the way to Ops.
Let's see if we can get
these doors open.
Dukat, we're running
out of time.
I am almost done.
I've got the emitters wired
into the control panel.
Now, all I have to do
is reattach them...
to the power grid,
like so.
All right.
I'm ready.
Brace yourselves.
( prolonged explosions,
electrical hissing )
( machinery powering down )
Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead, Major.
Oh, Commander,
am I glad to hear you.
What's your location?
Level 29, Section D.
What's your status in Ops?
We've got about ten minutes
before the main reactor core
overloads
and destroys the station.
The only way to stop it
is to disengage
the laser fusion initiator
at one of the control
junctions on level 34,
but the turbolifts
and transporters are off-line.
They'll never
get there in time.
But we might.
Major, Mr. O'Brien and I
will handle the reactor.
You begin evacuating
the station.
Get as many people as you can
to the Defiant
and the runabouts.
KIRA:
Understood. Good luck.
Jake, I want you to head
for Runabout Pad C.
It's too far.
I'll never make it.
Listen to me, Jake!
I'm going with you.
All right.
Let's go.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in seven minutes.
Tell me something
I don't already know.
KIRA:
Kira to Odo.
Go ahead, Major.
We're beginning
evacuation procedures.
The force fields
have been deactivated
and all the doors on the station
should be operable.
All except one.
It seems the force field
around my office
is still in operation.
I'll send a work team
down immediately.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in six minutes.
Are you telling me
we're the only ones
still locked in?
This force field must be
on a separate system
from the others.
But why go to
so much trouble
to keep people out of
the security office?
It's not to
keep people out.
It's to keep me in.
I suppose, during
the occupation,
the Cardassians considered
their Security Chief
a security risk.
And I know why.
Oh, do you?
It's because they knew you
were an honorable man--
the kind of person who
would do the right thing
regardless of
the circumstances.
And now, your integrity...
is going to get us
both killed.
I hope you're happy.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in five minutes.
Chief, did you
ever finish
those upgrades on
the deflector shields?
Yeah. Why?
We may not have time
to disengage the
fusion initiator.
What if we directed
the explosion
into the shields?
That's not a bad idea.
The shields are the only thing
on the station
that can absorb
that much energy.
That power surge we felt
must have blown out
one of the plasma conduits.
The corridor's completely
blocked for the next 50 meters.
Can't we get around it?
We don't have time.
There might be a way.
There's a maintenance conduit
adjacent to this corridor.
If it's not blocked,
we might be able to
get around the debris
and get to
the reactor control junction.
Give me a hand.
I can feel heat
through the door.
What's wrong?
See for yourself.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in three minutes.
I want you to wait here.
Ah, but...
I mean it
this time.
I'll go first.
Follow five
meters behind me.
If one of us runs
into trouble in here...
I know, I know.
The other one
keeps on going.
( cries out )
( yells )
( groaning )
O'Brien!
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in 90 seconds.
Sisko to O'Brien.
Chief, can you hear me?
Chief, answer me!
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in 60 seconds.
( groaning )
Warning. Main fusion reactors
will overload in 30 seconds.
( coughing )
Jake... I thought
your father told you
to stay out of there.
If you don't
tell him, I won't.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Main fusion
reactor overload.
( panting )
( sighs )
O'Brien to Sisko.
Chief, you're all right?
Yeah, looks like we all are.
Ah. It's about time.
All right, Quark,
you can leave now.
"A self-important
con artist
"who's nowhere
near as clever
as he thinks he is."
That's your official
security evaluation of me.
Quark, I told you
to stay away
from the computer.
Two hours ago,
you told me
I was the most devious
Ferengi you ever met.
I thought we
were going to die.
I was trying to be nice.
Name one Ferengi
who's more
devious than I am.
Grand Nagus.
All right.
Name another.
DaiMon Tye.
One you
personally know.
Your brother Rom.
My brother?
Your Uncle Frin.
Frin?
Your cousin, Gaila.
Gaila! The one
with the moon?