Too hot?
A little.
Ah.
Why don't you specify
a lower temperature?
No, no, no, no.
Coffee should be a little
too hot to drink right away.
Why?
Lt, uh, slows down
the experience
gives you time
to savor the taste.
Ah, yes...
taste.
Odo, I know you don't
need to eat, but did you
ever try it anyway?
Once.
Not long after I was
first able to assume
the humanoid form.
And?
And since I don't
have taste buds
it was very unsatisfying...
not to mention messy.
Messy?!
I'd rather not talk about it.
Major Kira.
How nice to see you again.
Tiron.
You left Quark's last night,
just when I
was about to buy
everyone another round.
I was devastated
that you didn't say good-bye
and we were having such
a pleasant conversation.
As I recall, you were the one
doing all the talking.
Well, in that case,
you have me at a disadvantage.
You know all about me and I
know next to nothing about you.
Uh... perhaps I should be going.
Oh, no. Stay.
This is Tiron,
a business associate of Quark's.
This is Odo...
my lover.
Well...
you're a very lucky man.
I'm a lucky woman.
Yes... we're both very lucky.
And you make a most...
interesting couple.
So, Mr. Odo,
what is it that you do?
I'm Chief of Security
on this station.
Oh.
A station this size
it must be
a very challenging job.
I hope you're well compensated.
Oh, money doesn't matter.
All we need is each other.
Isn't that right...
sweetheart?
Yes...
sweetheart.
You see, money isn't everything.
Oh, no,
but it can buy everything.
Well, I'm afraid
I must be going.
Good-bye.
Oh, good riddance.
Thank you, Odo.
Wish you'd been
around last night.
I better get back to Ops.
See you later, sweetheart.
Commander's Log,
Stardate 48423.2.
Despite the continuing threat
posed by the Dominion
I've convinced Starfleet
that we must continue
our exploration
of the Gamma Quadrant.
I've run a preliminary
analysis of our sensor sweeps
and the second planet
in the Kylata system
is definitely M-Class.
I wish we'd had time
to beam down to the surface
and take a closer look.
Yeah, but I'd hate
to have run
into a Jem'Hadar patrol
while we were down there
picking flowers.
Fortunately, there's no sign
of any Dominion activity
in this sector.
And let's hope
it stays that way.
I'm picking up very unusual
gravimetric distortions
in the Trialus system.
Any idea what's causing them?
It's hard to tell at this range.
Let's take a closer look.
The system's coming
into visual range.
On screen.
The gravimetric distortions
are intensifying
but they don't seem to be coming
from the star itself.
But where else
could they be coming from?
There aren't any planets
in this system.
There are now.
The planet seems to have settled
into a stable orbit.
But where did it come from?
Could the entire planet
have been cloaked?
If it was, there should be
residual ionization traces
but I'm not reading any.
Commander, we're being scanned.
The beam is coming
from a settlement
on the southern hemisphere.
I'm reading approximately
30 humanoid inhabitants.
They seem to be the only
humanoids on the planet.
They're hailing us.
Open a channel.
I'm Commander Benjamin Sisko
of the Federation Starbase
Deep Space 9.
I am Seltin Rakal of Meridian.
We were studying the star system
when your planet appeared.
I expect it must have come
as something of a surprise.
Well, you could say that.
It seemed to come
out of nowhere.
Not nowhere, Commander
but from a dimension
that intersects with this one.
I could explain more in detail,
if you're interested.
We were just about
to sit down for First Meal.
Why don't you join us?
We'd like that.
I just need to know
your planet is not
going to disappear
in the middle of dessert.
Don't worry.
We'll be here for a while.
It's good to be together
around this table again
after so long.
What's more,
we're fortunate to have visitors
to share First Meal with us.
I was admiring...
your markings.
Are they decorative?
No. Are yours?
No.
If you don't mind my asking...
how far down do they go?
All the way.
Ah.
You're not eating, Commander.
I guess my curiosity is
bigger than my appetite.
I hope we can satisfy both.
Hmm.
Well, you were saying
Meridian emerged
from a dimension that intersects
with this one?
Yes.
You see, our planet
has a dual existence.
It shifts between this dimension
and another.
What causes these shifts?
Well, we're not entirely sure.
Deral has been studying
the phenomenon.
With only limited success,
I'm afraid.
My theory is that the
dimensional shifts are caused
by fluctuations
in Meridian's quantum matrix...
fluctuations that are somehow
triggered by our own sun.
What's it like,
this dimension of yours?
It's hard to explain.
It's... without form.
We exist as pure consciousness.
And Meridian?
It becomes noncorporeal as well
but when we return
to this dimension
everything is just
as we left it...
the buildings, the trees,
even our bodies.
Are you saying
that when you return here
it's as if no time has passed?
We only age when we're
in corporeal form.
Sounds like this other dimension
has its advantages.
Yes...
but we always look
forward to this existence
and its many pleasures.
Oh, here, let me
help you with that.
The trick is
to scoop out the pulp
and eat the thin layer
inside the rind.
Here, try some.
It's delicious.
Especially if you've been
looking forward to it
for 60 years.
60 years?
Mm-hmm.
Huh. That's a long time
between meals.
A glass of Andorian ale.
Done so soon?
You were barely
in the holosuite ten minutes.
There was no reason for me
to stay the full hour.
I understand.
It's a very...
effective program.
On the contrary,
I found it to be
quite dull... boring,
boring, boring!
I'm sorry to hear you say that
but if you're asking
for a refund, forget it.
The contract specifically
says that satisfaction
is not guaranteed.
But... for a valued customer
such as yourself
I'll make an exception
and allow you to try
a different program...
no extra charge.
Let's see.
Something a little bit more...
unique?
Oh, I have just the thing...
"A picnic with
the Pleasure Goddess of Rixx."
I can even provide real food,
for a small fee, of course.
I don't like picnics, Quark,
and the food here is abominable.
Forget the food.
Believe me, you've never
had a picnic like this one.
What I want
is not in your catalog.
Well, tell me what it is
and I'll order it for you.
It may take some time,
but, if it exists, I'll get it.
That's just the point, Quark.
The program I want
doesn't exist.
Not yet, anyway.
A custom program...
it'll be expensive.
Oh, for that kind of money,
you can move into a holosuite.
Now, what is it you want?
I want...
Major Kira.
Kir...
What are you going to do
with Kira in a holosuite?
No... don't tell me.
I don't want to know.
Can you do it?
It isn't going to be easy.
I'll have to get her
into the holosuite
and record her image,
and she hates holosuites.
Spare me the details.
Do we have a deal or do I
take my business elsewhere?
Consider it done.
Now, I'll just keep this...
Payment on delivery
and not a moment sooner.
Don't disappoint me, Quark.
When I walk into that holosuite
and I see Kira standing there...
I'd better believe
it's really her.
Leave it to me.
Mm-hmm.
The things I do for money.
Just beyond that forest
there's a garden
with a small pond.
It sounds lovely.
It is.
Deral, our scans show
that there are
only about 30 of you
on this entire planet.
Well, there were
never many of us.
We're the descendants
of an expedition
that was stranded here
millennia ago.
And your population hasn't
increased since then?
It did for a time
but over the last few centuries,
our numbers have dwindled.
You see, we only reproduce
when we're in humanoid form
and our time here
keeps growing shorter.
In 12 days, Meridian will shift
back to its noncorporeal state.
And remain there
for the next 60 years.
Eventually, we will only be here
for a matter of minutes.
When that happens,
Meridian will be too unstable
to successfully shift back
to the other dimension.
And then what happens?
The planet
and all its inhabitants
will cease to exist...
in either dimension.
We deeply appreciate
your offer of help, Commander.
If there is a way to stabilize
the dimensional shifts
we'll do everything
we can to find it.
That's all we can ask.
Aha. Here you go.
Do you want to play
vajhaq with us?
Maybe later.
Deral and I are beaming
up to the Defiant.
We're going to run a series
of helio-seismic scans
on the Meridian sun.
I'll join you.
Good luck.
Dabo!
Quark.
I got a message that Morn
wanted to see me.
I'm afraid you just missed him.
Really?
So soon?
Would you come with me, please?
Listen up, everyone.
I have wonderful news.
It's my pleasure to announce
that my one-millionth customer
just walked through the door.
And here she is,
ladies and gentlemen
Major Kira Nerys.
Quark! I don't
have time for this.
Why don't you make him
your one-millionth customer?
But, Major, that
would be dishonest.
That never stopped you before.
But this is
a special occasion.
An event like this only happens
once in a bar owner's lifetime.
Let me tell you
about your prizes.
You mean, I won something?
Of course, you won something.
It's part of the celebration.
I never won anything before.
Well, now you have.
Congratulations.
Are you really
serious about this?
My customers are
my livelihood, Major.
This is a chance for me
to give something back to them.
Now, let's see
what we have for you.
A bottle of Kandora champagne,
vintage 2368...
that's a very good year.
These are good for five
free spins at the dabo wheel.
And last but not least
one free hour in a holosuite
with the program of your choice.
Wait... a visit to a holosuite?
Offer good today only.
But that's perfect.
Right this way.
It's Ensign Quintana's birthday.
He'd love a free visit
to the holosuite.
But, Major, what about you?
Oh, you know how I feel
about the holosuites, Quark
but, uh... thanks
for the champagne.
These are the Defiant's
sensor readings
when we first
entered the system.
Take a look
at the spectral scan.
It indicates that your sun
was giving off
modulated gamma bursts
right before Meridian
appeared.
My people have no record
of that phenomenon.
That's not surprising,
since Meridian was
in a noncorporeal state
when it occurred.
Gamma activity
would seem to indicate
an anomaly
in your sun's fusion cycle.
Let's find out for sure.
Chief, I want you
to send a probe
into the sun's corona
to scan the core.
It'll take a minute to modify
the shield configuration.
How do modulated gamma bursts
cause a dimensional shift?
Do you always do that
when you're concentrating?
Do what?
Bite your lower lip.
I guess I do.
Probe's ready, Commander.
Target it to these
coordinates and launch.
Shields are holding.
It's going to be a while
before the probe starts
sending back any telemetry.
Well, I'm sure you have
things you need to do.
Not really.
What a coincidence.
Neither do I.
This isn't turning out
exactly the way I planned.
What do you mean?
You've barely spoken a word
since we left the settlement.
I don't know
if you noticed or not
but Seltin didn't seem too happy
to see us leave together.
Well, she'd probably
prefer that I was...
walking with Keshara or Renar.
You see, ever since
my wife died
everyone's been wondering
when I was going
to find myself
another companion.
Why haven't you?
I guess I was waiting
for the right woman
to fall out of the sky.
That doesn't happen too often.
It only had to happen once.
Don't worry about Seltin.
After all, we both know
this is just a...
harmless little walk.
Absolutely.
With a brief stop
to climb a tree.
Come on.
Don't tell me
in eight lifetimes
you've never climbed a tree?
That's how I know
I'm afraid of heights.
Well, don't worry.
I won't let you fall.
This is one
of my favorite views.
It's hard to believe
that it all might
be gone in two weeks.
I hope not.
So do I.
We better climb down.
Oh, it's as beautiful
as you described.
I knew you'd like it.
Try one.
Mmm! That's wonderful.
I knew you'd like that, too.
You know me pretty well
for someone who just met me.
I'm glad you noticed.
I can't remember the last time
I did this...
stroll through a garden,
climb a tree
eat fresh berries by a pond.
What comes next?
I think I'm starting
to remember.
How are the
calculations coming?
I'm checking them now.
They're the same as before.
There's nothing to indicate
the gamma bursts
are causing
the quantum fluctuations.
Then something else
must be triggering
the dimensional shifts.
Whatever it is, we'll find it.
Sisko to Dax.
Go ahead, Commander.
Good news.
We've been able to get the probe
down another thousand kilometers
into the sun's corona.
We picked up
some additional telemetry.
I'll download it to you.
Thank you, Chief.
If all that fresh air
and sunshine
start getting to you
you're welcome to come
back up here to the Defiant.
We're managing just fine.
I'm sure you are.
Sisko out.
Don't you want to take a look
at the new telemetry?
I'd rather sit here
and look at you.
How about this?
We work for a few more hours
and then we go back
to your room
and count each other's spots.
Oh, can I go first?
We'll see.
Take a look at the fusion
reactants in the core.
They're out of balance.
That's right, and the
imbalance is building
toward a cascade reaction
on the quantum level.
That's what's triggering
the dimensional shifts.
And if we can stabilize
that reaction...
We can keep
Meridian here longer.
Oh, Jadzia!
I've got to get this
to Commander Sisko
and Chief O'Brien.
And then we can count
each other's spots.
These security protocols
look fine, Odo.
Just let me know...
Odo, move out of there.
You're ruining my shot.
Odo...
Oh, uh, Major...
uh, why is Quark
trying to take
a holo-picture of you?
Looks to me like he's
pointing at both of us.
True, but every time
I stand in front of you
he seems to get very upset.
Where are you going?
Uh-oh.
What do you think
you're doing, Quark?
- Nothing.
- Hah!
Then what's this?
Oh, you mean this holo-imager.
I was just recording
an image of the Promenade
to send home to my mother.
Hah!
You're trying to take
a holoscan of me
and I want to know why.
Of you? Not at all.
You just happened
to get in the frame.
Hah!
Will you stop doing that?
Not until you start
telling the truth.
You want the truth?
I'll tell you the truth.
I was trying to get
an image of you
for a special holosuite program
I'm designing.
Oh, I can just imagine
what kind of program
that would be.
I'm sure you can,
but you'd be mistaken.
The fact is,
I'm working on a simulation
of the station's
Operations Center.
People want to know
what goes on up there
and they want
to imagine themselves
fending off a Cardassian attack
or facing a fleet
of Jem'Hadar ships.
Naked, I assume.
Isn't there some petty thief
you can harass?
Just you.
What do you say, Major?
Give the public what they want.
They're not asking for much...
just the chance to work
side by side with you.
Oh, they want to work with me?
Well, then let them apply
to the Bajoran Military Academy.
That way, I can be sure everyone
in Ops is wearing their uniform.
Is that a no?
Well, let me put it
another way...
if I ever catch you pointing
a holo-imager at me again
you will end up eating it.
Definitely a no.
Jadzia.
I've been looking for you.
You found me.
I have.
Good news... it's going to work.
We'll be able
to equalize the time
between dimensional shifts.
Oh, Jadzia, that's wonderful.
Do you know
what I'm going to do?
I'm going to build a house
right here.
Nothing extravagant.
Just big enough for two.
Deral, I...
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking
this man that just met me
is talking about
building a home for us.
I realize you have
a life on Deep Space 9
but now, you'll have
a place here as well...
for when you visit.
I won't be able
to visit for a while.
It's going to take a long time
to stabilize the sun's
cascade reaction.
How long?
Meridian is going
to shift in five days.
Jadzia...
We'll see each other again.
In 60 years.
I want you with me now.
That's what I want, too,
but there's nothing we can do.
Yes, there is.
I can leave Meridian
and go back
to the Alpha Quadrant with you.
If you'll have me.
What do you think?
Deral!
We've been looking for you.
Commander Sisko told us
the great news.
I can't thank you enough
for all you've done.
I'm glad we were able to help.
The next time
Meridian returns here
we'll have 30 years
for our people to get
to know each other better.
I need to discuss
something with you.
Of course.
I've called a meeting.
Now that we have a future again
we need to start
planning for it.
And you need to make
some decisions as well.
That's what I want
to talk to you about.
The person you need
to talk to is Keshara.
She's not going to wait
for you forever, you know.
I was going to speak
to her as well.
I'm glad.
Think of it, Deral...
people can start
having families again.
Eventually, we may have
to expand the settlement.
As you can see, Jadzia
we have a great deal
of planning to do.
Well, I think
I've kept the others
waiting long enough.
Come, let's get started.
You'd better go inside.
I'll meet you back at the ship.
You know, the person
I feel sorry for is Quark.
He always thought that you
and he were made for each other.
I don't suppose
he'll be letting you
win at tongo anymore.
What are you talking about?
He doesn't let me win.
Come in.
Deral.
Well, it's done.
I told Seltin and the others
that I'm leaving Meridian.
Oh, what did they say?
They asked me not to go.
Seltin feels the settlement
can't afford to lose anyone.
What did you tell her?
I told her I understood
her concern
but that I've made up my mind.
So, what were you two talking
about before I interrupted?
Not me, I hope.
Well, actually,
I was just telling Jadzia
that, uh, not as good a tongo
player as she thinks she is.
Tongo?
It's a game,
and I'm very good at it.
Well, we'll find out
on Tuesday night.
And I want you there
to see for yourself.
I'm going to clean you
and Quark out.
Jadzia, I have to go.
But you just got here.
There are some things
I need to take care of
before we leave Meridian.
Do you need any help?
No, I...
I just have to say
good-bye to some people.
I'll see you later tonight.
Tiron, I was just
thinking about you.
And I was thinking about you,
and your reputation
as a man who can get
anything for a price.
Stop. You're embarrassing me.
I'll embarrass you even more
if you don't get me my program.
Not to worry.
Is that it?
No.
It's a high-level
decryption protocol.
And I'm using it to get
the final information
I need for your program.
It cost me dearly.
If it works, it's worth
whatever price you paid for it.
I was hoping you'd say that.
I'll put it on your bill.
Fine. Just get me my program.
I'm leaving in two days.
You'll have it, and I assure you
it'll be well worth the wait.
I'll stake my reputation on it.
You already have.
Now...
where to begin, hmm?
You wanted to see me?
Yes.
Someone has been
illegally accessing
the station's personnel files...
your file, to be exact.
Mine?
They've downloaded
your voice print,
your retinal scan
even your psychiatric profile.
I've managed to trace the data
path back to its source.
Well, let me guess... Quark.
Was there any doubt?
Oh, with all this information
he'd have no problem generating
a holo-image of me.
So, shall I arrest him or would
you prefer to do it yourself?
No, I have a better idea.
Can you spare a few hours?
I'd like to prepare
a little surprise for Quark.
You see, the key
to tongo is to confront
when you're sure
you're in a better position
than the other players.
And if your cards
match the roll of the dice
then you win.
Deral...
Go on, I'm listening.
You haven't heard a word
I've been saying, have you?
I'm sorry.
I just have so much on my mind.
You don't want to leave
Meridian, do you?
I said I would and I will.
I know what you said,
but what do you want?
To be with you.
But you're worried
about your people.
There are so few of us, Jadzia
and now that Meridian has
a future again, they need me.
Then you have to stay.
And lose you?
No.
What if you didn't
have to lose me?
What if I stayed here with you?
I wish you could,
but that's not possible.
Your molecular structure
wouldn't survive
the dimensional shift.
We could use
a transporter buffer
to match my quantum matrix
to yours.
But how do you know
that's possible?
Because I discussed
it with Julian
after you left my quarters.
Jadzia...
are you sure
you're willing to do that?
It's the only way
we can be together
and I don't want
to lose you either.
Come in.
Benjamin, I was just
finishing up my request
to Starfleet
for my leave of absence.
I bet this is the first time
anyone has requested
a 60-year leave.
You'll be sure
that it gets to them?
If you're sure that this
is what you really want.
What I really want
is for you to say
that you're happy for me.
I guess I just need to know
that you have thought
this thing through.
If Curzon had told me
he wanted to go off
with some woman he just met
I would have tried
to talk him out of it, too.
And you would have been right.
He fell in love with someone new
every other week.
But I'm not Curzon.
No...
and I've never seen
Jadzia do anything
without thinking it through
first.
I am happy for you.
It's just...
I'm going to miss you, old man.
You've been my friend
for two lifetimes.
I can't imagine what
it's going to be like
not having you around.
And leaving Deep Space 9
is the hardest thing
I have ever done
but I know it's right.
Besides, after eight
lifetimes as a humanoid
existing as pure consciousness
might be interesting.
Next time we see each other
I'll probably be
a great-grandfather.
Good. Then I can
call you "old man."
I'll look forward to it.
Now, I believe we agreed
I'd be paid on delivery.
I haven't seen
the merchandise yet.
You know, Quark
if this program is
as good as you claim
I might just purchase it
from you to use at home.
You have your own holosuite?
Just a little present
I bought myself.
His very own holosuite.
Hmm.
It's good to have money.
I've been waiting for you.
Quark!
I will ruin you for this, Quark!
You mean you didn't
like the program?
I don't know how,
I don't know when
but I will ruin you.
Wait!
What about my money?
Another satisfied customer,
Quark?
How do you feel?
Pretty good, considering
I spent six hours
having my molecules scrambled
in the transporter.
I, um...
I don't know what to say.
That's a first.
According to Deral's
calculations
the dimensional shift
should occur
within the next 47 minutes.
Do you think you'll be done
overhauling the station
by the next time I see you?
I doubt it.
Tell Quark I'll be back
to collect
the three strips
of gold latinum he owes me
with 60 years' interest.
Energize.
I was beginning to think
you were having second thoughts.
No, just saying good-bye.
You missed Last Meal.
I saved you some of these.
Thank you.
Jadzia, I just
wanted you to know
how happy we are you've
decided to join us.
Thank you.
Everyone's beginning to gather.
It's almost time.
Is there anything I need
to do to prepare?
Not that I can think of.
What if I just hold onto you?
After all, we're not
going to be together again
like this for a long time
and... I was just
getting used to this.
We'll still be together,
Jadzia...
in a way you can't even imagine.
There she goes.
Good-bye, Jadzia.
Something's wrong.
Commander, I'm reading
intense seismic activity
throughout the planet's crust.
It better shift soon or it's
going to tear itself apart.
Jadzia.
I'm picking up
some kind of singularity
in the planet's quantum matrix.
It's interfering
with the dimensional shift.
It's functioning
almost like an anchor.
Commander, it's Dax.
Her presence there
is destabilizing the matrix.
Sisko to Dax.
Get her out of there, Chief.
I thought you'd like to know
that Meridian shifted normally
once we beamed you away.
Ah... good.
Jadzia...
I'm sorry.
Benjamin, don't.
There's nothing you can do.
Uh, I just need some time.
Just 60 years or so.