Kira, we've got
six Byzatium transports
coming in this afternoon.
I've got to have
more cargo space.
All right, have them off-load
into Cargo Bays 3 and 4,
but that's it.
We are pushing
our storage capacity as it is.
Well, that reminds me...
we got a message last night
saying the Byzallians
want to move their
conference up by a week.
I haven't had a chance to read
through last night's reports.
Is there anything else
I should know?
Well, um...
What?
Starfleet wants
a complete report done
on our computer
calibration subroutine.
The whole subroutine?
When?
Tomorrow.
Major, the scheduled transport's
been delayed
and I need those medical
supplies by the end of the week.
We can't spare a runabout
to go all the way
to Vulcan right now.
I'm supposed to be setting up
a field hospital
for a new colony
on Campor III next week.
And if I don't get
those medical supplies
then the entire
colonization schedule
could be set back
by at least...
Listen to me!
You can't have a runabout.
You cannot get
your medical supplies
and I don't give a damn about
the colonization schedule!
Those colonists can make do
with a box of bandages
for all I care.
Stop right there!
Major.
When was your last day off?
I don't know.
What does that have to do
with anything?
If you can't remember,
then it's been too long.
You're off duty,
as of this moment.
What do you mean I'm off duty?
You can't do that.
Oh, yes, I can,
and not even Commander Sisko
can overrule my judgment
as Chief Medical Officer.
Now... now, wait a minute,
Julian.
Just because I snapped...
My diagnosis is
that you are overworked
and suffering
from extreme stress
and borderline exhaustion.
As for my prescription...
Follow me.
Karvino juice
Lorvan crackers
a holosuite program
a jumja stick
and gambling tokens.
Now, at least two of these items
must be used and fully enjoyed
before you leave this facility.
Julian, I...
I'll be giving you a full report
of her activities, Doctor.
And if I hear you
didn't completely relax
and enjoy yourself tonight
we'll do this every night
until you do.
Have fun!
Looks like you've got
your evening all planned.
Hope you've got room
for the unexpected.
Welcome aboard, Commander.
Thank you.
Call me Will.
What brings you to Deep Space 9?
Strictly pleasure.
Actually, I have built up
about three months of leave
and Dr. Crusher finally insisted
that I take some of it.
She nearly shoved me
out of the airlock.
Well, DS9 isn't exactly
known as a vacation spot.
Actually, I was just passing
through on my way to Risa.
The last time I was here
I was only able to spend
a couple of hours at Quark's.
But, by the time I left,
I had all of his latinum
and a date
with one of his dabo girls
so I thought
I might try my luck again.
You be careful.
Quark's dabo wheel's been
a little stingy lately
and one of his dabo girls
is dating my son.
In that case, I think I'd better
spend my time in the holosuite.
It sounds safer,
all the way around.
Who's in there?
What?
Who's in with Benjamin?
Oh, it's Will... Commander
Will Riker from the Enterprise.
Will Riker?
You know him?
Yeah.
I met him a year ago at Quark's.
He's, uh, quite a dabo player.
Hmm.
Do you know him?
Yes, a little.
I met him at Quark's last night.
You met him last night, and?
And we talked.
And then?
And then we talked.
For three hours.
No, we just talked.
And, yes, he's a warm,
charming man...
but I'm involved with someone.
Of course.
So why do you keep glancing
back at Sisko's office?
If you can find the time
you have an open invitation
for dinner with me and Jake.
Thank you.
I may take you up on that.
I hope you're not here
for another loan.
Don't tell me you've forgotten
who staked you
three strips of latinum
when your winning streak
ran dry.
I'm sorry.
Of course.
Most of that night's
still a blur.
How have you been, Dax?
Fine.
Well, I'd better
get out of your way.
I know you all have work to do.
Hope to see you again.
Major.
Commander.
- Oh!
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
My mind was a million
light-years away.
I should have been paying
attention to where I was going.
You doing some shopping?
Well, actually, I was just
exploring the Promenade.
I'd thought
about going into Quark's
but I wasn't really in the mood.
Where are you off to?
I'm just getting off duty.
I was about to call it a night.
Oh, I see.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Commander?
Would you like a tour
of the station?
I'd love one.
Where should we begin?
We can walk along the Promenade
for a start.
There's quite a bit to see here.
You think we might get a chance
to look at that new starship
of yours?
What do you call it, the...
Oh, the Defiant.
Yes, the Defiant.
I understand
it's quite a vessel.
I'm sure that can be arranged.
Please identify
for access to USS Defiant.
Major Kira Nerys,
Bajoran militia.
Identity confirmed.
Commander William Riker,
Starfleet.
Identity confirmed.
Chief, I didn't know anyone else
was on board tonight.
Oh, I hadn't planned to.
Ouch!
I was just getting
a little extra work done
on the deflector
targeting arrays.
Commander...
I'd heard you were aboard
but I-I hadn't...
There's nothing to say
to you, O'Brien.
I think you know why.
Well, maybe we should
come back another time.
No, no, no, Major,
it's all right.
I was just leaving.
Commander.
What was all that about?
Ah, it's a long story.
I'd rather not get into it.
Let's take a look
at this ship of yours.
Okay. I'll, uh, show you
the tactical systems first.
Think you're going
to be surprised
at how big a punch
this little ship has.
Running the plasma conduit
through your primary
phaser coupling
has almost doubled
your phaser power.
Doesn't that cut into
your warp drive efficiency?
Not at all, in fact,
it's 30% more efficient.
That's ingenious.
I'd like to see
how it's all routed
through the tactical display.
Command authorization required.
New security procedure.
Computer,
release Bridge lockout.
Authorization:
Kira Delta-5-4-7-Alpha.
Thank you.
Ah!
What's going on?
I'm not sure,
but something happened
to the warp core on the Defiant.
It looks like it's going
to breach in 57 seconds.
Anyone on board?
O'Brien was working
there this morning
but I don't know if he...
Incoming signal
from the Defiant.
It's Commander Riker.
On screen.
Commander Sisko,
there's been an accident.
One of the plasma conduits
has exploded.
Major Kira has been injured.
We are 45 seconds
from a core breach.
Release the docking clamps.
I will get us away
from the station.
We'll beam the two of you out of
there as soon as you're clear.
Docking clamps released.
I'm engaging thrusters.
15 seconds.
Lock on and beam them away,
Chief.
I can't get a lock.
The Defiant's shields are up.
What?
She's gone into warp.
I've lost them.
We're beyond their sensor range.
Lay in a course
for the Badlands, warp seven.
Tamal, secure that conduit.
Right.
Course laid in.
We'll be in the Badlands
in six hours.
You did it, Tom.
It's not over yet.
Nine years ago
a transporter accident
created two William T. Rikers.
One of them returned to his ship
the other was marooned
on Nervala IV.
The second Riker was finally
discovered two years ago.
He chose to use
his middle name, Thomas
to distinguish himself
from the other Riker.
The two men are physically
identical in all respects
right down to their DNA coding.
There was no way
for the security computer
to know that it was
Thomas, not William
who boarded the Defiant.
This is
a very entertaining story
but... why am I listening to it?
We have reason to believe
that Thomas Riker
is a member of the Maquis.
What?
Thomas Riker was serving
aboard the Starship Gandhi.
While he was there,
he began to express
certain political opinions.
Opinions that supported
the Maquis and their goals.
Are you telling me...
that one of the most heavily
armed warships in this Quadrant
is now in the hands
of Maquis terrorists?
Do you have any idea
what kind of response
this will provoke
from the Central Command?
They'll probably want
to send ships
into the Demilitarized Zone
to conduct a search.
We understand that
but any entry into the Zone
must be a joint operation
between Cardassia
and the Federation.
The Central Command
will not be interested
in any joint operation,
Commander.
They won't believe your story
about transporter duplicates
and security failures.
They will assume that Starfleet
wanted the Maquis
to have the Defiant
and they will respond
accordingly.
And what does that mean exactly?
It means they will seize
this opportunity
to finally eliminate the Maquis.
They will send a fleet
into that Zone.
Starfleet will cooperate
in a search for the Defiant
but they will not allow
the Central Command
to use this as an excuse
for a full-scale invasion.
Of course not.
So you will send your
own fleet into the Zone
to protect Federation colonies.
But, at some point,
the two fleets will meet
tensions will rise,
nerves will fray
and someone will make
the tiniest mistake.
And we'll have a war
on our hands.
It is a prospect
I do not relish, Commander.
Neither do we.
That's why we need
to work together
to prevent it from happening.
Well, unless I can bring
something back to Central
Command to prove your good faith
and your willingness
to help stop the Defiant
I don't believe anything
can prevent this conflict
from beginning.
Then bring me with you.
I can help you stop the Defiant
and prove our good faith.
I was in charge of the shipyard
where the Defiant was built.
I helped design it.
I know her vulnerabilities
and her weaknesses.
You'll help us destroy
one of your own ships?
I want to try
and disable it first.
Oh, I'm sure you do.
But you are in no position
to bargain here, Commander.
You want to prevent a war
you come back to Cardassia
with me, and you help me
destroy the Defiant.
I don't care who you are
or what your name is.
I am sorry about lying to you,
and I'm sorry about using you.
It was an operational necessity!
You were a resistance fighter.
You know that certain times
you do things
that you're not proud of
to accomplish the mission.
Well, you accomplished
your mission, so now what?
Everyone's going
to be looking for you.
The Cardassians and Starfleet.
How far do you think you're
going to get with this ship
before they find you?
A lot farther
than people anticipate.
Kalita to Riker.
We've reached
the rendezvous point.
I'm on my way.
The other Maquis ships
just arrived.
The rest of the team's ready.
Lower the shields
and beam them aboard.
The Maquis ships
are heading for the border, Tom.
All defense systems on line
and operational.
Warp power standing by.
Lay in a course for the
Cardassian border, warp eight.
Course already laid in.
This ship was built to fight.
I think it's time
she got her chance.
Engage.
Commander's Log,
Stardate 48467.3.
Gul Dukat and I have arrived
on Cardassia Prime.
I'm about to do something
which goes against 20 years
of Starfleet training...
help an enemy hunt down
one of our own ships.
This is where I'll be conducting
the search for the Defiant.
From this room, I can control
every Cardassian ship, outpost
and space station
anywhere in our...
Ah, Commander, allow me
to introduce Korinas
our observer
from the Obsidian Order.
Commander Sisko.
Korinas.
Welcome to Cardassia Prime,
Commander.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Secure that console
while the human is here.
Anything else classified
level 4 or above
should also be secured.
I'm sure you can understand
that although we all respect
Gul Dukat's decision
to bring you here,
we must take some precautions.
Of course.
I would have done the same.
But then...
I would have been more discreet.
Since you are here
to provide technical expertise
on the Defiant
I suggest you begin
by briefing us
on the ship's
defensive capabilities.
Please, describe for us
in detail
the weapons systems
of the Defiant
beginning with
the ship's phaser array...
Before we discuss weaponry,
there's a more urgent matter
that I think
you should be aware of.
The Defiant is equipped
with a cloaking device.
I wondered
if you were going to share
that little detail with us.
You knew about this?
The Obsidian Order
has known for some time
about the loan
of a cloaking device
from the Romulans
to the Federation.
And the Order chose not
to share this intelligence
with the Central Command?
Until now, the Order had
not considered this one cloak
to be a threat
against Cardassia.
Under our terms of agreement
with the Romulans
the cloaking device
was to be used
only in the Gamma Quadrant,
and then only in exchange
for all our intelligence
reports on the Dominion.
Well, your Lieutenant
Riker isn't likely
to respect that agreement
with the Romulans
and there's no way
to locate a ship under cloak.
There is one possibility.
The Dominion managed
to penetrate the cloak
by using some kind
of antiproton beam.
Can you give us the
specifications of that beam?
Not precisely,
but I can give you
everything we've learned
from our sensor logs.
It'll give you a chance
to find the Defiant
before she attacks.
We're approaching
the security perimeter, Tom.
All right, this is it.
Red Alert.
Cloak the ship.
Stand by, weapons.
Squadron Baker has arrived
at their checkpoint.
Transmit the go-ahead signal.
We'll be in Cardassian
sensor range in five minutes.
There is a perimeter alert
in the Almatha sector.
Put it on the main viewer.
Who's commanding the outpost
nearest that ship?
Gul Toran of the Sixth Order.
And he's identified the vessel.
It's the Defiant.
Order all warships
in that sector to converge
on the Defiant.
Something's wrong.
Why wouldn't they be cloaked?
Can you show me the sensor
information on the Defiant?
The Defiant is
attacking Outpost 61.
Tell Gul Toran
that he has permission
to pursue the Defiant
into the Demilitarized Zone.
No, don't pull your ships
off the border.
Commander, you don't expect me
to break off pursuit
of the Defiant
simply because the treaty's...
That's not the Defiant.
It's a decoy.
They're trying to draw your
patrol ships out of position.
That ship's sending
out a fake warp signature
identical to the Defiant's
but the phase variance and
subspace harmonics don't match.
Order Toran
to break off pursuit.
Have him redeploy...
Sir, another perimeter alert.
Outpost 47 has detected
a cloaked ship
with their antiproton beam.
Tell Toran to head
for Outpost 47.
The Defiant has de-cloaked
and has begun
to attack the outpost.
We've lost contact
with Outpost 47.
Incoming message from Gul Toran.
The Defiant has re-cloaked
and its last known heading
was 148 mark 215.
It's headed directly into the
heart of Cardassian territory.
Commander Sisko,
you should be commended.
I only wish we had someone with
such keen tactical instincts
who could have prevented
this invasion of our territory.
We're past
the security perimeter
out of their sensor range.
They're using antiproton beams
to scan for us.
Adjust the cloak's
resonance frequency
so they can't detect us again.
- Right.
- Damage report.
We took six hits
on the port shields.
There's been some minor damage
to the outer hull,
but all systems are operational.
Tough little ship.
Set a course for the shipyard
at Omekla III.
We'll let that be the place
that...
Report.
We've lost main power,
and the cloak is off-line.
Looks like two plasma
conduits blew out.
Where?
Deck 3, section 15.
Crew quarters.
Looks like
Major Kira's been busy.
You crossed the replicator
power converter
with the plasma manifold,
I take it.
That's right.
Nice work.
You know I'll have that thing
bypassed in 30 minutes.
At least that'll be 30 minutes
that we're visible.
Fortunately, I was able
to take us into a nebula.
No one's going to see us.
Thanks.
You're lucky
you only got singed.
You know, the whole plasma relay
could have exploded.
Yeah, that was the idea.
You've been fighting Cardassians
most of your life.
I know that you sympathize
with what we're doing here.
I fought the Cardassians
because they invaded my home.
You don't live
in the Demilitarized Zone.
You don't have family there.
Why are you in this fight?
Because people are dying
in the Demilitarized Zone
and Starfleet isn't doing
anything about it.
Taking the Defiant
only raises the stakes.
The Cardassians are going
to send a fleet after you.
They are going to kill
more people hunting you down
than they ever did
during those border raids.
You're assuming
the Defiant is going to stay
in the Demilitarized Zone.
Let's go to the Bridge.
I think we'd all feel better
having you someplace
we can keep an eye on you.
15 outposts have checked in.
No sign of the Defiant.
26 warships have scanned
14 cubic light-years of space
with antiproton beams...
no Defiant!
What are the possibilities?
They're still under cloak
and heading deeper
into Cardassian space.
They're laying low
and waiting
for some unknown reason.
Dukat.
Hmm?
Are you listening to me?
Oh, I'm sorry, Commander.
I was thinking
about my son's birthday.
Really?
Yes, today is his 11th birthday.
Oh.
I'd promised to take him
to the amusement center
in Lakarian City.
He always wanted to go...
but I never had the time.
I told him, "This year
will be different, Mekor.
This year,
I will make the time."
I had the same experience
with Jake.
At that age, they never
understand, do they?
You just hope that,
one day later
they'll look back and say
"Now I understand.
Now I know why he did that."
When my son looks back
on this day
the only thing he'll remember
is that a Federation officer,
on a Federation ship
invaded his home
and kept his father away
from him on his 11th birthday
and he won't look back
with understanding.
He'll look back with hatred...
and that's sad.
The cloak is operating
within normal parameters
but the plasma conduit damage
has caused a slight neutrino
leak in the port nacelle.
The Cardassians might
be able to detect it
even through the cloak.
A chance we have to take.
Lay in the course
for Omekla III.
Engage at warp eight.
Warp eight.
Aye, sir.
Omekla III?
You're headed for the shipyard?
There have to be
half a dozen better targets
in this sector alone.
I hope the Cardassians
have the same reaction.
"What is he doing?
And why?"
All right, now you're trying
to keep them off balance,
keep them guessing.
Why?
The Maquis
have been hearing rumors
about shifting loyalties
in the Cardassian government.
Certain hard-line elements
were unsatisfied
with the Federation treaty
and are doing whatever
they can to scrap it.
We got our hands
on an intelligence report
outlining suspected military
buildup in the Orias system...
a secret buildup that even the
Central Command isn't aware of.
You're telling me
you did all of this
to attack some secret base
that may or may not exist?
I'm convinced that it does.
They are building
an invasion fleet.
If we let them finish it
these renegade Cardassians
are going to use it.
You're really not cut out
for this, are you?
Being a terrorist, I mean.
You're not very good at it.
Really?
You're acting more like
a Starfleet officer
who's more interested
in intelligence reports
and Cardassian politics, than
in actually hurting Cardassians.
You have one
of the most powerful ships
in this Quadrant
under your command.
Why aren't you out attacking
every Cardassian outpost
along the border?
Because these stakes
are far greater
than border outposts.
Not for the Maquis, they're not
because the Maquis
are terrorists
and the only thing
terrorists care about
is attacking the enemy.
I know...
I was a terrorist
and if I had had this ship then
I would have destroyed
Deep Space 9.
I would have hit
the Cardassians so hard
they would have
screamed for peace.
But I certainly wouldn't
have gone flying off
into the middle of Cardassia
on some wild-goose chase.
I guess we're different
kinds of terrorists.
No...
you're trying to be a hero.
Terrorists don't get
to be heroes.
We'll see.
This is how
your ships were deployed
before the first Defiant attack.
And this is where they are now.
Don't you see what happened?
Each Defiant attack
was designed
to draw your ships
away from that sector
leaving it virtually
defenseless.
But there's nothing
of any value in that sector.
There must be something.
Are there any M-Class
planets there?
Well, there's one...
Orias III, but it's uninhabited.
It's desolate.
But everything seems to point
to the Orias system.
It might be worth your sending
one of your warships there
just in case
the Defiant does show up.
All right.
Contact Gul Ranor.
Tell him to dispatch
one warship...
No.
You'll send no ships
to the Orias system.
You're here as an observer.
You have no authority.
That sector is
under direct control
of the Obsidian Order
and you will not enter it.
Why?!
That matter's classified.
Well.
You can file a complaint
with the Central Command later.
Open a channel
to Gul Ranor now.
Any warship sent
into the Orias system
will be destroyed.
Are you saying
that you will fire
on another Cardassian ship?
What I am saying is
that the Obsidian Order
will take whatever steps
are necessary
to protect the Orias system.
And so will I.
I've spoken to a few friends
in the Central Command.
The Obsidian Order isn't giving
them any answers, either.
The Order has to answer
to someone.
In theory, they answer
to the political authority
of the Detapa Council
just as the military does.
In practice, we both
run our own affairs.
Not a very efficient system.
It's worked
for over five centuries.
There's an incoming message
from the Warship Kraxon.
They say they've found
an unusual neutrino signature
in their sector.
It looks like radiation
from a damaged
warp plasma relay.
Is this signature moving?
No, but they're scanning
their area
with their antiproton beams.
Where is the Kraxon?
If it is the Defiant,
they're in position
to make a run
for the Orias system.
We still don't know
that Orias is the target.
Until we do, I can't risk
pulling ships away from
other potential targets
to chase down
a neutrino signature.
They're coming around
for another pass.
Are there any other ships
nearby?
There are nine
Galor-class cruisers
about six light-years away.
Any ships between us
and the Orias system?
No.
If you make a run for it
that ship out there's
going to see
our neutrino signature
go through a phase change.
They're going to call
their nine friends
and you are going to have
a small fleet
chasing you
all the way to Orias.
They can chase me
all they want...
as long as they don't catch me.
The Kraxon reports
that the neutrino signature
has just phase-shifted
and is moving now at warp speed
directly
toward the Orias system.
Order the Kraxon
to pursue at maximum warp.
Order all other ships
in the sector to follow.
The Kraxon is pursuing
but they won't catch us
before we reach Orias.
Full scan.
I want to see everything
that's in that system.
When you make out your report
for the Obsidian Order
be sure to mention the fact
that I could have prevented
the Defiant from reaching Orias,
if you hadn't interfered.
They will never reach Orias.
You can count on that.
Three more ships
have just appeared
in the Orias system.
What kind of ships?
Cardassian warships...
Keldon-class.
Whose ships are those, Korinas?
Why are you asking me?
Because if they
were military ships
I would know about them.
So that leaves
the Obsidian Order.
I thought the Obsidian Order
didn't have any ships.
They're not supposed to.
In fact, they are
explicitly forbidden
from having military equipment
of any kind.
It looks like we're going to
have to fight our way to Orias.
Listen to me.
Those three ships up ahead
are going to lock onto our
neutrino leak and open fire.
That means you're going
to have to fight back.
With this ship, it'll be a short
fight, I promise you that.
Let's say you disable
or even destroy, those
three ships up ahead of us.
Fighting them at all
is going to slow us down.
And then those ten ships
behind us
are going to catch up.
And not even the Defiant
can win against those odds.
We have come too far
to quit now.
You are an experienced
Starfleet officer, Tom.
Analyze the situation.
Going to Orias is suicide.
Now, the smart move is to make
a run for it while we still can.
Maybe that's what an experienced
Starfleet officer would do
maybe that's what
Will Riker would do
but it's not
what I'm going to do.
I'm going to continue
the mission.
It's not the mission
you're thinking about, is it?
Or even the colonists
in the Zone.
This is about you, isn't it?
You and that other Will Riker
out there.
The man with your face,
your name, your career.
You are looking for a way
to set yourself apart.
Some way to be different.
You shouldn't go fishing today.
You won't catch anything.
Take us in.
You want to know what's going on
in the Orias system
I know how you can find out.
Give Riker a chance
to surrender.
The Defiant's scanned
the Orias system by now.
Its sensor logs can tell you
everything you want to know.
I'd be happy to accept
his surrender
but I doubt he'll be willing
to hand over his logs.
He will, if you agree
to release Major Kira
turn the ship and the Maquis
over to the Federation.
Impossible!
I cannot allow a group
of terrorists
to just walk away
after invading our territory...
Then you must decide
which is important to you...
your sense of Cardassian justice
or the information contained
in the Defiant's sensor logs.
I do want that information,
Commander
and I would be willing
to return your wayward ship
but someone has to pay
for what's happened here
and I don't want
that someone to be me.
If you return the Maquis
to the Federation
I can promise you
that they will stand trial
for what they've done.
A Federation trial.
It's the best I can do.
All right.
I would be willing to hand over
Major Kira, the Maquis
and the ship
but not Riker.
He led the mission.
If I can bring him to justice
and obtain the information
on Orias
that might be enough
for Central Command.
I might be able to get him
to do it, on one condition.
We both know
that Cardassian sentences
are determined
well in advance of the trial.
I'd like you to arrange
a sentence other than death.
I'll have to clear that
with the Ministry of Justice.
You'd better make it quick.
We're approaching
the first cruiser.
They'll be in phaser range
in 15 seconds.
Go to impulse.
De-cloak the ship.
Raise shields
and stand by phasers.
Go to heading 118 mark 310.
Lock on phasers.
Fire.
Direct hit on the cruiser's
port nacelle.
Their shields
are down by 30 percent.
We've been hit
on our starboard shield.
Shields holding.
Quantum torpedoes...
full spread.
Torpedoes locked on target.
Fire!
Their defense systems
are off-line
and they've lost main power.
Tom, three more cruisers
have just appeared
in the Orias system.
That makes five ships
ahead of us and ten behind.
Resume our original course
to the Orias system.
Stand by emergency
power to the shields.
Incoming message
from Cardassia Prime.
It's Gul Dukat
and Commander Sisko.
On screen.
This is Gul Dukat
of the Second Order.
I am authorized to tell you
that if you surrender your ship
none of you will be harmed.
Is that right?
Listen to him, Lieutenant.
If you surrender,
the Defiant and its crew
will be handed over
to a Federation starship
at the Cardassian border.
Why the sudden generosity?
He wants the Defiant's sensor
logs on the Orias system.
They're worth a lot more
to him than Maquis prisoners.
I don't buy it.
The Cardassians aren't going
to just let us walk away.
You're right.
Someone has to pay the price.
Me.
The deal is
you'll be tried and convicted
in a Cardassian court
and then sentenced
to spend the rest of your life
in the Lazon II labor camp.
No death sentence, huh?
That must have taken some doing.
Some.
Give me a moment.
Tom.
There's no reason
for you to continue.
They're offering you a way out.
The only reason not to take it
is because you want to die.
I have a mission to complete.
That mission is over.
You're never going
to make it to Orias.
You know that, Tom.
There are five ships
out there ahead of you
but there may be 50 waiting
there, for all we know.
Be a Starfleet
officer one last time.
Think of your crew.
I know you want Tom Riker
to go out in a blaze of glory
that they talk about
for the next ten years.
Don't drag them along with you.
On screen.
I agree to your terms.
You need to reverse course
and surrender the Defiant
to one of the ships
that's been following you.
Why?
It will take too long to explain
but the ships coming out
of the Orias system
are not
under Gul Dukat's control.
I see.
I've ordered the Kraxon
to put her shields around you
as soon as you arrive.
You'll be safe
once you get there.
Understood.
Turn us about.
Lay in a course for the Kraxon.
Do it.
Those are faster
than any Keldon-class ships
I've ever seen.
What is going on in that system?
We're 100 million kilometers
from the Kraxon.
Incoming message.
Let's hear it.
This is Gul Ranor of the Kraxon.
Cut your engines in five seconds
and we will extend
our shields around you.
Acknowledged.
Kalita.
All stop.
They won't fire
on another Cardassian ship.
They can't.
They're moving off.
They've set course
back to the Orias system.
Transmit the Orias III
sensor logs to the Kraxon
and tell them to prepare
to beam me aboard.
I'm turning command over
to Major Kira.
She'll get you back
to the Federation.
I'm holding you
personally responsible
to see that these people get
a fair trial.
I give you my word.
We'll get you out of there, Tom.
I promise you that.
Riker to Kraxon.
Go ahead.
One to beam up.
Set course for the Federation.
Warp eight.