( door opens )
( door closes )
I didn't expect to find you here.
I thought you'd be down on the Promenade
helping Mardah put up the decorations
for the Bajoran Gratitude Festival.
That was the plan
but it turns out I don't have
much to be grateful for.
-Isn't that the earring you--
-Bought for Mardah, yeah. You want it?
Maybe you can give it to Major Kira
for her next birthday or something.
( sighs ) All right.
Tell me about it.
Mardah's gone, Dad.
She got accepted to the Science Academy
on Regulus III.
That's a good school.
It's 300 light-years away.
Jake, you're 16.
Take my word for it, you'll survive.
Sooner or later, you'll find someone else.
Who knows?
Maybe you'll find someone tonight
at the Gratitude Festival.
Yeah, sure.
Jake, the whole point of the festival
is to put all your troubles behind you
and make a new start.
I could use one.
-OK, I'll go.
-Good. That's the spirit.
But I'm not going to have any fun.
Oh.
( laughs ) Nervous, Chief?
( laughs )
What are you talking about?
That's your fifth cup of coffee
in 20 minutes.
I didn't realize you were keeping track.
Oh, nervous and irascible.
If you hadn't seen your wife
and child for two months,
you'd be irascible, too.
Oh, believe me, I'm looking forward
to Keiko and Molly's visit
as much as you are.
I doubt that.
How many games of racquetball
have we played in the last two months?
I don't know. 15, maybe 20.
No, try 70.
I've been keeping track of that, too.
You know what all those games
have proved to me?
That I'm a poor substitute for your wife.
I could have told you that 60 games ago.
Thing is, they're only going
to be here for two days.
That's barely enough time to say hello.
And they're back to Bajor again
for another four months.
Four months?
Why, that's another
150 games of racquetball.
I don't think my elbow
can take that kind of abuse.
Maybe you can try
and convince her to stay.
No, no, I can't do that.
I mean, I'm the one who suggested she go
on this agrobiology expedition
in the first place.
No, we'll just have to make
the best of the little time we have.
Which means we can't waste
a second of the next two days.
Ah, peldor joi, Odo.
Peldor joi to you, too, Major.
Well...
It's, uh...
It's hard to believe
the Promenade is this empty at midday.
Oh, calm before the storm.
In a few hours, this place will be packed
with Bajorans celebrating the festival.
Actually, I was thinking
of joining you this year.
Really?
I don't see why not.
None of my Bajoran deputies
work during the Gratitude Festival.
Why should I?
Besides, if I'm going to
live here with you humanoids
I may as well immerse myself
in your rituals.
Well, then, we'll see each other later.
I'd like that.
If you're not too busy
being the Presider at the festival.
For you, I will make the time, Odo.
Just look for me. I'll be with Bareil.
Oh...
I thought he'd be celebrating
the festival on Bajor.
So did I. I'm glad I was wrong.
He's arriving on the next shuttle.
Well... you'd better go.
It'll be here soon.
You're right.
-I'll see you at the festival.
-Ah.
Chief.
Major.
-Keiko.
-Ah... Bareil.
-Good luck.
-You, too.
Nerys...`
I am so glad to see you.
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
Miles.
Miles!
Oh, Keiko.
I'm so glad to see you.
I have had the worst trip.
Oh, really? I'm sorry to hear that.
Now that you're here
everything's going to be great.
Hello, sweetie.
You ready to have
a great time with your dad?
No.
Why not?
I don't feel so good.
Really?
Aw... tell Daddy what's wrong.
-( retching )
-Ah!
( gasps ) Oh...
LWAXANA: Oh... you poor dear.
I should never have given you
all that candy.
I usually make it a point
to drop by Quark's
three or four times a day
at random intervals.
Just to let him know
I'm thinking about him
but seeing today is a holiday
he'll be busier than usual.
I suggest you station
a man there full time.
I think that about covers it.
If you need me, I'll be on the Promenade.
LWAXANA: But don't call
unless it's an emergency.
The Constable will be occupied.
ODO: Madam Ambassador.
Oh, do we have to be so formal?
Didn't they teach you any manners
in Starfleet Academy?
Be a dear, run along.
The Constable and I have
a lot of catching up to do.
Uh, come back in five minutes.
Make that half an hour.
So...
what brings you to the station?
Well, officially I'm here
as the Betazoid representative
to the Gratitude Festival
but the truth is, I came to see you,
you poor, sweet, tortured man.
Excuse me?
Oh, well, I know the torment
you must be going through.
Well, to spend your whole life searching
for your people,
only to discover that they're the leaders
of that awful Dominion.
You heard about that.
Odo...
don't worry.
I'm here to help you.
What kind of help do you mean?
Oh, a sympathetic ear...
a shoulder to cry on...
a lap to melt in.
Ah.
Well, that's very considerate of you,
but unnecessary.
My people are who they are.
I am who I am.
I've learned to accept that.
Oh, you brave soul.
Oh, why don't we go someplace quiet
and you can tell me all about it?
Actually, I was planning
to attend the opening
of the Gratitude Festival this afternoon.
Oh...
Well, even better.
First, a little fun and relaxation
and then we can delve
into the depths of your pain.
I'll freshen up and meet you
in front of the Bajoran Temple
for the Presider's opening address.
I promise you, Odo,
you'll never be alone again.
( beep )
Level 23, Section 8.
Oh!
We need to see each other more often.
Hmm, I wish we both weren't so busy.
I never expected Kai Winn to make me
one of her principal advisors.
I think she asks your advice
just so that she can do the exact opposite
of what you recommend.
I know you don't like Winn
but the office has changed her.
The Prophets chose well.
So, why don't we leave
spiritual matters in their capable hands
and uh, concentrate on enjoying ourselves?
I have to go.
The festival doesn't start
for an hour.
But I have to set up the Renewal Scrolls
along the Promenade
but it won't take long.
Jadzia's promised to help me.
Hmm. Jadzia, of course.
I've never understood
how the two of you
could be such good friends.
She's so...
Unpredictable.
And you're so...
Predictable?
I didn't mean it like that.
It's just that she gets to spend
so much more time with you than I do.
Jadzia and I have been doing this
for the past two years.
It's becoming a tradition.
I was hoping we could start
a few traditions of our own.
We will... later tonight.
( sighs )
( exhausted sigh )
Is she asleep?
It looks like the medicine
Doctor Bashir prescribed is working.
Ooh, that's a relief.
( sighs )
Rough trip?
Oh, it was a disaster.
I thought it would never end.
Well...
I'm glad you're home.
Me, too.
We should get ready for the festival.
The baby-sitter will be here any minute.
Oh, the festival.
On the other hand...
We could spend the rest of the day
locked away in our quarters.
Miles, what I really want to do is sleep.
Well... then maybe you should.
Miles, I didn't say I was going to.
I just meant I could use some.
That's OK.
If you need to sleep, go ahead.
-I'll understand.
-No, you won't.
You'll be disappointed
and you'll start brooding
and stomping around like an Andorian bull.
Look, go or stay, sleep or don't.
It's all the same to me.
Just tell me what you want to do,
and we'll do it.
Miles, I've been making decisions
all day long.
You decide.
OK.
We'll go to the festival
but we don't have to go right away.
I mean, you can take time to relax
and then change into something nice.
Nice?
Yeah.
Like your red dress.
My red dress? Really?
Is there something wrong
with your red dress?
No. It's, it's...
Just a little tight, that's all.
Oh. That's why I like it.
All right. If it'll make you happy,
I'll wear the red dress.
Look, forget the red dress, OK?
Just wear whatever you want.
Look...
Let's just try to enjoy the next two days.
I'll change into something nice
and we'll go to the festival, OK?
Fine.
( door opens, closes )
( sighs ) I can hardly wait.
( indistinct conversations )
( ringing continues )
( speaking native language )
( applause )
And now I have the honor
of placing the first
Renewal Scroll into the fire.
As the scrolls burn
may our troubles turn to ashes with them.
( cheering )
And now, for the next 26 hours
I expect you all to enjoy yourselves.
I know I will.
May the Prophets walk with us.
( woodwinds playing )
( groaning )
Jake, are you all right?
Uh, just felt funny there for a second.
You're sure you're all right?
Yeah, Dad.
Never felt better.
Bareil? What are you looking for?
Hmm? Oh, nothing.
Just... just looking.
Hmm.
Peldor joi.
Oh, Jake, how thoughtful. Thank you.
Uh, I know you're busy
but can I talk to you for a second?
Sure.
In private. It's kind of personal.
Oh, um...
I'll be right back.
Now, Jake, what can I do for you?
Uh...
I need some advice.
You see, there's this older woman
and I think we're perfect for each other.
Ah... and she doesn't.
I don't know what she thinks.
Well, Jake, my advice to you
is to tell Mardah how you feel.
-That way you'll know--
-Mardah and I broke up.
You broke up?
Well, then, who?
You.
Me?
I love you, Nerys.
Want to go out with me?
Morn, it's hard to believe
a handsome, fun-loving guy like you
could have so many problems.
My advice to you is to burn this
as quickly as possible
and don't look back.
Sage advice.
Vedek Bareil. It's good to see you.
Oh, you have such a wise, generous spirit.
I only wish I had a friend like you.
I think of you as a friend.
You mean that?
Of course.
Oh, I'm glad because I was hoping
that you and I could get
to know each other a little better.
A lot better.
Excuse me.
( music playing )
I love Bajoran music.
It's so intelligent, so vital...
It reminds me of you.
Oh, dance with me, Odo.
I'm sorry. I don't dance.
Nonsense.
I saw you moving to the music.
That wasn't dancing.
That was... swaying.
Oh...
then sway with me, Odo.
Sway with me.
I just remembered. I'm needed in Security.
( sighs )
I'll come with you.
Ah, hello, Lieutenant.
-Having a good time?
-No.
( grunts in agreement )
That's right.
Genuine latinum-plated
Renewal Scroll inscription pens
blessed by Vedek Redab himself
shortly before he passed away.
Each pen is engraved with the words
"Deep Space 9's Third Annual
Gratitude Festival,"
today's date, and a lovely portrait
of the station by Ermat Zimm.
So, get them while you can!
They're sure to become collectors' items.
( indistinct conversations )
Oh!
So...
What do you say we take a walk
around the Promenade for a while?
I'd rather stay here.
I-I never thought I'd say this
but I kind of miss Quark's.
The noise, the excitement...
our table.
You know...
I haven't sat here since you've been gone.
Oh, that's so sweet.
So, how's the survey been going?
Uh... the terrain's
rougher than we expected
and the ecosystem's a lot more diverse
than it looked from the orbital scans.
All in all, it's been pretty grueling.
Really?
Don't get me wrong.
I'm having a wonderful time.
That's good.
There is one problem
I have to talk to you about.
It looks like the project's
taking longer than we hoped.
What do you mean, "longer"?
You have to understand, Miles,
every valley has
an entirely different ecosystem.
There's a lot of work to be done.
But how much longer is it going to take?
I'm... I'm not sure.
Try a guess.
Uh, you know, an extra couple of days?
A week? Two?
More like two or three months.
You're telling me
you're going to be on Bajor
for another seven months?
It's either that or ask them
to find another botanist.
Maybe that's something worth considering.
-Are you asking me to resign?
-No...
but seven more months?
I don't like this any more than you do.
You just said you were
having a great time.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I suppose you'd be happier
if I were miserable?
I didn't say that.
( sighing ) Sebarr was right.
I never should've mentioned it.
Who's Sebarr?
He's one of the zoologists
I'm working with.
He warned me not to talk to you about this
until after the Gratitude Festival.
And who's he to be giving you advice?
He's a friend.
A friend?
I thought you were down there working.
We are working.
Yeah, with time out for intimate
little chats about our relationship?
What else did you tell him about us?
Miles, you're behaving like a child.
What do you want me to say?
I want you to say
that you're not going back...
that you're going to stay here with me.
Miles, right now I don't even want
to sit at the same table with you.
Fine.
Well, go on.
Leave.
Go back to Bajor and your plants
and Sebarr.
See if I care!
Whoa!
Slow down.
Hi, Dad.
I've been looking all over for you.
In case you've forgotten,
we're hosting a Gratitude Dinner
tonight in the Wardroom.
I could use your help in getting ready.
I'm kind of busy right now, Dad.
I-I have to find someone.
Oh, Major Kira?
-How'd you know?
-I just spoke to her.
-Really? Where is she?
-Ah, just hold on!
But I have to talk to her.
You know, you were right about me
meeting someone at the festival.
I did not mean Major Kira.
-You like her, don't you?
-Well, of course I like her.
Well, so do I.
( sighs ) Jake,
what you're feeling now is just a crush.
Look, Jake...
Right now,
you are confused, vulnerable, hurt.
You miss Mardah.
Mardah was a mistake.
She was too young, too immature for me.
Major Kira is a woman.
Major Kira is in love with Vedek Bareil.
It won't last. He's always on Bajor.
She needs someone who can
be with her all the time, like me.
( sighs ) Jake,
I don't want to see you hurt again.
I appreciate that.
But this is between Nerys and me.
Don't worry.
Everything's going to be fine.
Thanks.
I really can't accept this.
But I want you to have it.
It's my gift to you.
Well, that's very thoughtful of you
but I have nothing to give you in return.
Being with you is the only present I need.
Now, come on.
Let's go write our Renewal Scrolls.
Peldor joi, Chief.
You look terrible.
It's just a little headache, that's all.
Here. Have a free pen.
What for?
To write down your problems
on a Renewal Scroll.
There isn't a scroll long enough
for all my problems.
Really? I thought you could sum them up
with one word...
Keiko.
Tell me I'm wrong.
If you ask me, it's your own fault.
You never should have let her
go to Bajor in the first place.
What was I supposed to do?
Force her to stay here with me?
That would have been a good start.
You hu-mans, you never learn.
You let your women go out in public,
hold jobs,
wear clothing,
and you wonder why your
marriages fall apart.
That's your solution, Quark, huh?
Treat women like property?
Criticize it all you want,
but on the Ferengi homeworld
husbands and wives never argue.
There's no divorce, no broken homes...
Nothing but peaceful conjugal bliss.
If Ferengi marriages are so wonderful
why are you still single?
I haven't met the right woman yet.
Well, I have.
She just walked out that door.
And out of your life.
Not if I can help it.
Bareil!
I was wondering where you disappeared to.
Come on, you can do better than that.
Someone might see us.
We are the only people here.
Everyone else is on the Promenade.
We have two hours before we're supposed
to join Commander Sisko for dinner.
That gives us some time
to be alone together.
I... I can't. Um...
Why not?
I have to find Jadzia.
Jadzia? Is there something wrong?
No, not at all.
Do you know where she is?
She's probably on the Promenade.
She wasn't there the last time I looked.
Why is it so important
for you to see Jadzia?
I'll explain everything later.
Uh...
Thank you, Nerys.
For what?
For being such a good friend.
Friend?
Dax...
what are you doing here?
I thought you might need some help
getting ready for the party.
Thanks, but that won't be necessary.
Wouldn't you rather be celebrating
on the Promenade?
No, thanks. I don't want to run
into Vedek Bareil.
Oh, is there a problem between you?
He can't keep his hands off me.
That doesn't sound like Vedek Bareil.
I couldn't believe it myself
but he wouldn't leave me alone.
He's probably still out there
looking for me.
Have you told Kira?
I don't know how.
It's going to break her heart.
( sighs ) Someone has to tell her.
Do you want me to do it?
Would you?
Well...
if you think that's the
best way to handle it.
( sighs )
I'd really appreciate it, Benjamin.
I mean, this whole thing is ridiculous.
How could I be interested in Bareil?
We both know...
It's always been you.
( stammering )
Dax...
Hmm?
-What are you doing?
-Making myself comfortable.
Have I ever told you
that you smell wonderful?
Ah, you know, old man, I have to admit
you had me going there for a minute.
Benjamin, stop acting so coy.
There's no one around.
I have an idea.
You cancel the party, and then, that way
we can spend the evening alone together.
-What do you say?
-Oh... uh...
-Sisko to Bashir.
-BASHIR: Go ahead, Commander.
Meet me in the Infirmary immediately.
Aye, sir.
BASHIR: Her vital signs are normal.
Her brain activity is normal.
No sign of infection or intoxication
of any kind.
She's the picture of health.
DAX: Told you.
Then why did you put
your head on my chest?
Oh, Julian, you should have seen his face.
Admit it, you were
this far away from total panic.
BASHIR: I think we've both been
victims of a practical joke.
At least someone around here
has a sense of humor.
Um, see you at the party, Julian.
I've never been so embarrassed
in all my life,
making me go through all those tests.
It's your fault, Dax.
You took this one too far.
Oh, if I didn't love you so much
I'd be angry with you.
See you at the party.
( sighs )
You look like you could use
a little cheering up.
-Jake, do me a favor.
-Anything.
Leave me alone.
Uh...
( sighs )
( door opens )
-Hi, sweetie.
-Hi.
-Feeling better?
-Lots better.
Ah, that's what I wanted to hear.
( snorting )
-Where's Mommy?
-In her room, sad.
Oh. Well, listen,
why don't you go and play with Piggy
in your room for a while
and we'll see if Daddy
can cheer Mommy up, huh?
Keiko, it's me.
Can I come in?
Not now, Miles.
You're right.
I'm an idiot... sometimes.
If I don't get my own way
I can be selfish
and childish and pigheaded.
I said some things to you
that were pretty stupid.
I wish I could take them back.
But even if it's too late for that, I...
There's one thing
I want you to know, Keiko...
I... I love you.
I always have and I always will.
I want you to know
I've left a letter of resignation
on Commander Sisko's desk.
I'm ready to move down to Bajor
with you tomorrow
if you'll have me.
And after that,
if you want to move back to Earth
that's OK, too.
I'll do whatever it takes.
I just don't want to lose you.
Honey, did you hear what I said?
Yes.
And?
And I need time to think.
Why don't you go
to Commander Sisko's party?
We can talk when you get back.
If that's what you want.
-Major...
-Ah!
Aren't you headed in the wrong direction?
-Commander Sisko's party?
-Oh, I'm not going.
-Why ever not?
-Because Bareil will be there.
I thought the two of you
were very happy together.
So did I, but it turns out
he'd rather be with Dax than me.
And to make matters worse,
I have Jake Sisko chasing me
around the station
professing his undying love.
BASHIR: Well, that's strange.
A little while ago
Jadzia had Commander Sisko convinced
that she was in love with him.
He even had me examine her
to make sure she was all right.
Apparently, it was only a joke.
Well, are you sure?
People are acting very strangely today.
Maybe I should take another look
at Jadzia's test results.
Excuse me.
Constable, would you tell Commander Sisko
that I'll be a little late?
Oh, I should be getting to the Infirmary.
I'll join you.
( groans ) Maybe you should examine
Bareil and Jake while you're at it.
That wouldn't be a bad idea.
Oh, this won't take long.
Oh, what is it, Odo?
I may not be able to read your emotions
but I can read your expression.
-Something's wrong.
-I'm fine.
I wish you'd tell me what's bothering you.
Maybe it would help you.
As soon as something bothers me
I'll let you know, I promise.
Why do I find stubborn men so attractive?
( groans )
( sighs )
Would you please stop following me?
Oh, gladly,
if you'll just stop running away.
I-I-I have something very important
to talk to you about.
Discuss it with Major Kira.
I'm not interested.
But, Dad,
you promised that Nerys would be here!
She will, and stop calling her Nerys.
( gasps )
Peldor joi.
Oh, Commander, I didn't realize
that you and Lieutenant Dax
were that close.
We're not.
Sisko to Bashir.
Computer, locate Dr. Bashir.
COMPUTER: Dr. Bashir is in the Infirmary.
( sighs ) Constable, go get Dr. Bashir
and bring him here immediately.
I'll be right back.
I'll go with you.
Yes, of course you will.
I wonder what Commander Sisko wanted.
Oh, it can wait.
This is very embarrassing.
Yes, we have to stop.
Definitely.
Doctor!
Commander Sisko needs to see you
in the Wardroom.
Oh, tell him...
Oh, tell him I'll be there shortly.
Now, Doctor!
You'd better go.
( moans amorously )
Right.
Peldor joi.
Please, Commander, step aside.
I need to speak to Jadzia.
I don't think she wants to speak with you.
DAX: You tell him, Benjamin.
I... I only want to give her this.
A Bajoran betrothal bracelet?
It's been in my family for generations.
Can I see that?
I...
Nerys! Am I glad to see you.
Doctor... I need your help!
And I need yours, too.
You've got to get me away from Kira.
I can't... ( gasps )
keep my hands off of her.
What's worse
I can't keep my hands off him.
( door opens )
( sighs )
I can't explain it either.
( gasps )
( sighs )
She doesn't love me.
Who?
Nerys.
( sighs )
You're better off.
In the end, they only break your heart.
( door opens )
Although, sometimes it's worth it.
What do you think?
You look beautiful.
Did you really mean it
about turning in your resignation?
Mm-hmm.
Well, you'd better get it back
before Commander Sisko sees it.
It was very nice of you to offer.
I love you so much.
( laughing ) Hey!
( lasciviously ) Oh...
Ooh...
Commander, here's that
I'danian spice pudding you ordered.
I want to give this to you
as a token of my affection.
Oh, no, you don't!
Bareil, listen to me...
I'll fight for her if I have to!
( grunts )
Oh, I'm sorry, Benjamin.
He was just starting to annoy me.
QUARK: Commander...
You throw one hell of a party.
Pudding, anyone?
I've got I'danian spice pudding.
( Bareil groans )
Are you all right?
( groans )
Pudding, anyone?
Doctor?
-Pudding, anyone?
-No, no, thank you.
Ooh!
( groans )
I'll take one.
Help yourself.
Why did she hit me?
( gasps )
Oh, forget about him.
What about me? I need you, Keiko.
My ears tingle at the sight of you.
Marry me.
She's taken, Quark!
( squealing )
Easy, Chief.
He doesn't know what he's doing.
What are you looking at me for?
Zanthi fever?
Oh, that's ridiculous.
That, that's impossible.
That only affects older Betazoids.
Well, that may be,
but according to my tests
you show all the symptoms.
Zanthi fever is a virus
which affects the empathic abilities of...
um... mature Betazoids.
It causes them to project
their emotions onto others.
Then Mrs. Troi's amorous feelings
for... someone on the station
were being passed along
to the people around her?
Well, not everyone.
Only those within close proximity to her
when she had an attack,
and even then
there would have had to have been
some preexisting latent attraction.
-You're saying Dax...
-Only on a subconscious level.
Best not think about it too much,
if you ask me.
I am terribly sorry, Commander.
I hope I haven't caused too much trouble.
I'm sure no permanent harm
was done, right, Doctor?
Oh, a simple wide-spectrum antiviral agent
should cure Mrs. Troi.
And as for everyone else
well, they'll be back to normal
in a day or two.
Excuse me.
I promised Nerys that I'd meet her
in her quarters this evening.
I think you ought to postpone that visit
for a day or two.
( sigh )
SISKO: Commander's Log, supplemental.
I'm happy to report
that Dr. Bashir's diagnosis
has been proven correct.
My son and all the others affected
by Mrs. Troi's condition
have made full recoveries.
( Troi laughing )
This is one Gratitude Festival
they'll be talking about for a long time.
I know I'll never forget it.
I hope everything
works out for you, Odo...
with Major Kira.
I... don't know what you mean.
Oh, don't worry.
Your secret's safe with me.
After all, I know what it's like
to be attracted to someone who doesn't
necessarily feel the same way.
( sighs )
If you get tired of waiting for her...
...you know where to find me.
I'll keep that in mind.
So, you're sure Dr. Bashir said
your test results were negative?
That's right.
My headache was just a headache.
I never was affected by Mrs. Troi.
Well, I guess that means you don't have
a latent attraction to me, after all.
Nothing latent about it
or weren't you paying
attention last night?
I was paying attention.
You still have the touch, O'Brien.
So do you.
You take good care of Mommy, honey, OK?
I will.
We'll see you in a few months.
I'll be here.
Chief?
( both laughing )