SISKO: Commander's Log,
Stardate 48481.2.
My senior staff and I
have been asked
to address the annual
Starfleet symposium
on the current situation
in the Gamma Quadrant.
I'm looking forward
to the opportunity
and to visiting
my sister in Portland.
Entering Earth orbit.
Now there's something I never
get tired of looking at.
If you ask me, the seas
could be a little more purple.
That's funny, I was just
thinking they weren't
green enough.
I guess it's true
what they say.
"There is no place
like home."
No matter what color
the water is.
We'd better get ready,
Benjamin.
Dinner tonight
with Admiral Drazman.
Oh.
Not "Droner" Drazman?
The Commander of the Proxima
Maintenance Yards?
BASHIR: You're more than
welcome to come along.
The entire senior
staff was invited.
Full dress uniform?
Fine table linens?
A different fork
for every course?
Thanks, but
no thanks.
That's why I stayed
an enlisted man.
They don't expect me to show up
for these formal dinners.
Major, Constable,
would you care to join us?
No, thank you.
I'd say this is strictly
a Starfleet occasion.
Commander, I'm receiving
an incoming emergency message.
- It's from DS9.
- On screen.
Commander,
am I glad to see you.
KIRA: This better
be good, Quark.
You're on an emergency channel.
I just received a message
from the Grand Nagus.
He wants me to remind you
of the critical role he played
in establishing contact
with the Dominion.
SISKO: You can assure the Nagus
I will mention his assistance
prominently in my report
to Starfleet.
There is one more thing,
Commander.
It seems the Nagus' nephew,
Belongo is currently being held
by Starfleet authorities
on Aldebaran III.
A slight misunderstanding,
I'm sure.
A misunderstanding the Nagus
no doubt wants to be cleared up.
I do owe him a favor.
He thinks so, too.
And to quote
the 111th Rule of Acquisition...
"Treat people in your debt
like family-- exploit them."
I have been reading up.
You can tell the Nagus
I will do everything I can
but also remind him of the
217th Rule of Acquisition...
"You can't free a fish
from water."
I'll be sure the Nagus
gets the message.
She's all yours, Major.
Energize,
Mr. O'Brien.
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
That's strange.
What's wrong?
Well, nothing serious.
Just a power fluctuation
in the annular
confinement beam.
Oh, well, that's impossible.
What happened?
Well, I stabilized the beam
but according
to our sensors
they never materialized
at their destination.
They're just... gone.
MAN: Okay, buddy, come on.
Rise and shine.
Come on!
Well, look what
we have here.
Who are you?
Who am I?
You believe this?
Sleeping Beauty
asking me questions. Up!
Hey, Vin, we've been
working all night.
Why don't we forget
about these guys?
I just want to go home
and see Sonya and the kids
and get some sleep.
What are you, an anarchist?
There's a law against
sleeping in the streets.
Though I do like
the matching pajamas.
All right.
Let's see some logo.
- Logo?
- VIN: I.D.
Identification.
UHC card.
Transit pass.
Where are we?
What happened
to Starfleet Headquarters?
Perfect. Just what we need,
two more dims.
Those shotguns, uniforms...
there's something
very familiar about this.
Yeah, probably from
the last time you were
in a Sanctuary District.
Sanctuary District?
What year is this?
Same year as it was yesterday--
2024.
Let's go.
VIN: How do they find us?
Are you okay?
Oh, my head.
What happened?
Did you get
jacked or something?
Jacked?
You know, robbed.
Oh...
Did they get your
credit chips, your I.D.?
(sighs)
Oh... it looks like
they got everything
except my brooch.
What...? Do you
live near here, uh?
Can you get home?
I was traveling
with some friends
and uh, I guess
we got separated.
Well, you shouldn't be
walking around without I.D.
You better order
some replacements.
You can use my Interface
terminal if you wish.
My office is just
around the corner.
That's very kind of you... um?
Chris, Chris Brynner.
Jadzia.
That's a pretty name.
What is that, Dutch?
Ah, something like that.
It's very kind of you
to help me.
Oh, don't mention it.
It's not every day that I get
to rescue a damsel in distress.
Let me help you.
It's just this way.
Check the Heisenberg
compensators.
I'll run a level-1 diagnostic
of the pattern buffers.
See if there was any
kind of field imbalance.
Chief?
- Any news from Starfleet?
- Nothing good.
As far as they can tell,
Commander Sisko and the others
never materialized
in San Francisco.
According to
their sensors
our transporter signal
disintegrated
immediately after we began
the beam-out sequence.
That doesn't agree
with our records.
The system log shows
that the transport
was successfully completed.
They definitely
materialized somewhere.
Well, that's
good news, anyway
- but the question is, where?
- Oh, I wish I knew.
Whatever the answer is,
it's not in the log.
The only unusual thing it
recorded was the variance
in the annular
confinement beam.
But you corrected for that.
It was a simple adjustment.
The beam was just reacting
to the accumulation
of chroniton particles
on the ship's hull.
Chroniton particles?
They're emitted
by the cloaking device.
They sometimes become lodged
in the ship's ablative
armor matrix.
But we've used the transporter
many times since the cloaking
device was installed.
There's never been
a problem before.
I don't know why
there should be one now.
Wait a minute.
It looks like there was
a surge in temporal energy
seconds before the initiation
of the transporter sequence.
Tell me that's a clue.
Oh, it's a clue, all right.
I just don't know
what it means yet.
BASHIR:
How do you feel?
Better.
Me, too.
Probably
transporter shock.
Disorienting, but it
wears off quickly.
I know one thing. We're
definitely in San Francisco.
I caught a glimpse of
the Golden Gate Bridge
a few blocks back.
I saw it, too.
Do you know what happened
to our combadges?
They were probably stolen
while we were unconscious.
This is not the Earth
we're used to, Doctor.
That's still at least
a century away.
I wonder what happened to Dax.
She was caught in the
transporter beam with us.
Whatever affected us,
must have affected her, too.
That means she's probably
somewhere nearby.
The first chance we get,
we've got to find her.
And then what?
And then, we find a way home.
VIN: All right, let's go.
Bring 'em.
Okay, let's go.
Hurry it up.
- Sonya's going to kill me.
- Eh.
What is this place?
A Sanctuary District.
BASHIR: 21st century history
is not one of my strong points.
Too depressing.
It's been a
hobby of mine.
They made some
ugly mistakes.
But they also paved the way
for a lot of things we now
take for granted.
- And I assume this is
one of those mistakes.
- A bad one.
By the early 2020s,
there was a place
like this in every major
city in the United States.
Why are these
people in here?
Are they criminals?
No, people with
criminal records
weren't allowed in
the Sanctuary Districts.
Then what did they do
to deserve this?
Nothing.
Just people...
without jobs or
places to live.
So, they get put in here?
Welcome to the 21st
century, Doctor.
VIN: Hold it right there.
You wanna go home, go home.
What do I care?
Thanks, Vin.
Shall we?
(knocking)
Hi.
Sorry to keep
you waiting.
Were you able
to order a new I.D.?
Just finished.
It took me a while
to convince them
I was who I said I was.
They'll be expressing
a transit pass
and a couple of credit
chips in a few hours.
I asked them to send it here.
- I hope you don't mind.
- No problem.
Thanks for letting me use your
terminal and your account.
You know, those are...
very unusual.
Oh, you mean my tattoos?
It is amazing work.
Where did you have them done?
Japan?
How did you guess?
Well, I used
to have one myself.
A Maori tribal pattern.
It used to go all
the way down my arm.
I got it in high school,
back in the '90s
just like
everybody else.
Of course, I had to have it
removed.
Well, you know how it is.
To get the government contracts
you have to look like
all the rest of the drones.
So I guess that
makes me a sellout.
Not necessarily.
What kind of business do you do?
You don't know?
Mm-mm.
Well, I guess I'll
have to have a talk
with my public relations people.
I'm Chris Brynner...
Brynner Information
Systems.
You know,
Interface operations
Net access, Channel 90.
That Chris Brynner.
(chuckles)
So, what do you think?
Does that make me
a sellout or not?
Probably, but I won't
hold it against you.
These friends of yours
that you told me about...
is there any way for you
to get ahold of them?
I wish I could.
VIN: Left hand.
Other hand.
Look straight ahead.
Now stand over here.
COMPUTER: Welcome to SafeTech's
fingerprint database.
Your government discount
has been accepted.
Remember, our new
retinal scan service
is now accessible
on Channel 178.
Yeah, yeah,
save the commercial.
COMPUTER:
We are sorry
but the fingerprints you have
provided are not on record.
No I.D.
No fingerprint record,
no Interface account.
It's like you two don't exist.
Well, since we don't exist,
why not let us go?
Yeah, well, let's see.
You don't have any I.D.,
you don't have any money
and you're both
dressed like clowns.
You figure it out.
Please fill out these forms.
Answer all questions
to the best of your ability.
If you cannot speak English,
an interpreter will be provided.
If you cannot read, questions
will be given to you verbally.
If there's any part of this form
you do not understand
ask one of our staff
for assistance.
Now, sit down, shut up
and fill out the forms.
And if you've got any problems,
don't come to me with them.
Thank you...
very much.
Tell Admiral Ngomo
I appreciate her offer
but I don't want anyone
beaming onto this ship
until we know
what's going on.
If they want to come up
by shuttle, that's fine.
Major, I think I know what
happened to Commander
Sisko and the others.
The temporal surge we detected
was caused by an explosion
of a microscopic
singularity
passing through
this solar system.
Somehow, the energy emitted
by this singularity
shifted the chroniton
particles in our hull
into a high state
- of temporal polarization.
- Which means what?
Which means the transporter
beam was redirected
as it passed through
the polarized particles.
- Redirected where?
- Not where...
...when.
The beam was redirected
through time, not space.
They arrived in San Francisco,
just like they were supposed to.
But not when they
were supposed to.
How much time are we
talking about-- days, weeks?
More like centuries.
This is ridiculous.
I mean, we've
been here three hours
and the line has
barely moved at all.
I got one word
for you, pal--
plenty of overtime.
That's three words.
Hey, for a dim,
you're pretty smart.
Now, go back and take a seat.
Oh, boy.
- (sighs)
- (woman shouting, indistinct)
Some of these people
are mentally ill.
They need proper
medical treatment.
I know, but they're
not going to get it.
Not now anyway.
What? What is it?
SISKO: That calendar over
there-- it says August 30, 2024.
I'm not sure I understand.
You ever hear of
the Bell Riots?
Vaguely.
It is one of the most
violent civil disturbances
in American history and
it happened right here,
San Francisco
Sanctuary District "A"
the first week of
September, 2024.
But that's only
a few days from now.
Which means if we don't
get out of here soon
we'll be caught right
in the middle of it.
Just how bad are these riots
going to be, Commander?
Bad.
The Sanctuary residents
will take over the district.
Some of the guards
will be taken hostage.
The government will send
in troops to restore order.
Hundreds of Sanctuary
residents will be killed.
Hundreds?
And there's nothing
we can do to prevent it.
Starfleet temporal
displacement policy
may sound good
in the classroom
but to know that hundreds
of people are going to die
and to not be able to do
a thing to save them.
I sympathize, Doctor, but if it
will make you feel any better
the riots will be one
of the watershed events
of the 21st century.
Gabriel Bell will see to that.
- Bell?
- The man they named
the riots after.
He is one of the
Sanctuary residents
who will be guarding
the hostages.
The government troops
will storm this place
based on rumors that the
hostages have been killed.
It turns out the hostages
were never harmed
because of Gabriel Bell.
In the end, Bell sacrifices
his own life to save them.
He'll become a national hero.
Outrage over his death and the
death of the other residents
will change public opinion
about the Sanctuaries.
They'll be torn down.
And the United States will
finally begin correcting
the social problems
it had struggled with
for over 100 years.
And all of this is going to
happen in the next few days.
Which means...
if we warn these people
about what's coming
if we try to help
them in any way
we risk altering a pivotal
moment in history
and we can't let that happen.
Hey, I hate to break up your
intimate conversation,
but you're next.
(phone ringing)
Is there something wrong?
Well, according to these forms
you're supposed to be dims
but you're not, are you?
I hope you're
not disappointed.
Pleasantly surprised
is more like it.
I guess I owe you an apology.
If I had known you were
gimmes I could've processed
your application much sooner.
Gimmes?
They're American
slang terms.
I try not to use them
but it's a bad habit.
Gimmes are people like you,
people who are looking for help.
A job, a place to live.
And what about the dims?
Don't they need help?
The dims should be in hospitals
but the government can't
afford to keep them there,
so we get them instead.
I hate it, but that's
the way it is.
I see here that you both have
just arrived in San Francisco.
Do you have any jobs lined up?
No. Um, actually,
we weren't planning
on staying here very long.
Have you got a place to stay,
or anyone who can vouch for you?
No, we were traveling with
a friend, but we were separated
right after we arrived.
You have any way of contacting
this friend of yours?
Not at the moment.
Well, in that case
I'm afraid you're going
to have to stay here
in the Sanctuary
for the time being.
You mean we can't leave?
It's for your
own safety.
Really?
And it's the law.
SISKO: What about jobs?
How are we supposed to
find a place to work
and somewhere to live
if we're stuck in here?
Well, one of the services
we provide is job placement.
And how long does
that usually take?
I wish I could give you
a definite answer
but jobs are hard
to come by right now
what with the
economy and all.
My advice is to be patient.
In the meantime, take these.
They're your
ration cards.
You can use them
to get food and water
at any of the distribution
points in the district.
Hang onto them.
Where are we supposed to stay
while we're here?
Anywhere you like.
The buildings in the district
are there for everyone to use.
Thanks for your help.
One more thing.
A little advice.
Stay away from
district security.
They've had their
budget cut again.
They're overworked
and underpaid.
Just give them a lot of space,
and watch out for ghosts.
- Ghosts?
- That's what we call people
who haven't integrated well
into the Sanctuary.
They can be dangerous
and they tend to prey
on other residents.
Thanks for the warning.
We'll stay away from them.
Dax to Sisko.
Dax to Bashir.
If you can hear me,
please respond.
Okay.
My assistant was
able to get you
a room at the Clift
for the next five nights.
You didn't have
to do that.
I know that,
but I wanted to.
So, uh, what
are your plans?
I still have to
find my friends.
Well, I hope
you don't mind
but I had Britt
do some checking.
No one matching their
descriptions has been admitted
to any of the city hospitals
- or trauma wards.
- That's good news.
Look, uh, I would like to know
how this turns out.
I'm having a little get-together
here tomorrow in the office,
and I'd like
you to come--
if you want-- you
and your friends.
I'd like that.
Well, good luck.
Thanks. I could use it.
Whoa. You guys
can't come in here.
BASHIR: We're just looking
for somewhere to sleep.
Well, you're going to
have to look someplace else.
Oh, let me guess--
this building is full.
Sorry.
Every building we go to,
it's the same story.
They can't all be full.
Don't be so sure.
One of the main complaints
against the Sanctuary Districts
was overcrowding.
It got to the point
where they didn't care
how many people were in here.
They just wanted to
keep them out of sight.
And once they were out
of sight, what then?
I mean, look at this man.
There's no need for him
to live like that.
With the right medication
he could lead a full
and normal life.
Maybe in our time.
Not just in our time.
There are any number
of effective treatments
for schizophrenia,
even in this day and age.
They could cure
that man now, today
if they gave a damn.
It's not that they
don't give a damn,
they've just given up.
The social problems they face
seem too enormous to deal with.
Well, that only
makes things worse.
Causing people
to suffer
because you hate
them is terrible
but causing
people to suffer
because you have
forgotten how to care--
(sighs)
that's really hard
to understand.
They'll remember.
It will take some time,
and it won't be easy
but eventually,
people in this century
will remember how to care.
Right, only it makes
you wonder, doesn't it?
Are humans really
any different
than Cardassians
or Romulans?
If push comes to shove,
if something disastrous
happens to the Federation,
if we are frightened enough,
or desperate enough,
how would we react?
Would we stay true
to our ideals
or would we
just stay here
right back
where we started?
I don't know.
But as a Starfleet officer
it's my job to make sure
we never have to find out.
(groaning)
MAN:
Get his food card.
Remember, Doctor,
we can't interfere.
You got a problem?
No problem.
MAN: You look upset.
If we've done anything
to offend you
please let us know, so that we
can be sure not to do it again.
Don't worry about us.
- We're new here.
- Really?
- I never would have guessed.
- (gang chuckles)
But let me be the first
to welcome you.
Would you like
a piece of this?
No, thanks.
Gimmes...
no sense of fun.
We're just looking
for a place to sleep.
Well, in that case...
you better look
somewhere else...
new boy.
You heard what he said.
Let's go.
Enjoy your stay!
And in a few days
I know you're going
to feel right at home.
Bye!
So, in theory, we should be able
to travel into the past
by focusing
the transporter beam
through the polarized
chroniton particles.
The problem is,
we don't know
where in time Sisko
and the others are.
I've narrowed it down
to a dozen different
possibilities,
but we only have enough
polarized chronitons
to make five or six attempts.
Then we'll have
to take our chances.
Pick the most
likely time periods
and send a team down with
tricorders to find them.
The hard part will be to find
a couple of volunteers
crazy enough to risk
getting lost in time
to do the job.
I think I know a few
likely candidates.
(scattered indistinct
conversations)
Here you go, Julian.
Oh... oh...
(coughs)
Oh...
If we ever get home
I promise never to complain
about the station's
Cardassian beds ever again.
(both chuckle)
Oh, where
is everybody?
In the food lines,
waiting for breakfast.
It's not much to look at
but it's better than nothing.
Uh, I'm sorry.
They ran out of utensils...
and napkins.
Why am I not surprised?
When you're finished eating,
I think we should get up on the
roof of one of these buildings.
I want to get a better
look at the place.
Do you think there's
a way out of here?
If there is, we'll find it.
Mm-hmm.
Hey.
MAN: Not you two
guys again.
Look, I told you,
we don't have any room.
We're not here to stay.
All we want to do is
- to get up on the roof and--
- It doesn't matter what
you want.
You can't come in.
We got to protect
what's ours around here.
Look, maybe we could
make a deal.
Isn't there something we could
exchange in order to get access
to the roof?
I don't know.
What do you got
to offer?
Uh-huh, that's
what I thought.
Look, maybe you guys should
try another building.
(whispers inaudibly)
Hey, uh... wait a minute.
Maybe... we can
make a deal after all.
(door shuts)
SISKO: Well, at least now
we look like we belong here.
BASHIR: Yeah, and we smell just
as bad as everyone else, too.
(moans)
Stay away from him!
Whatever you say.
Just put the
knife down.
Step into the light,
so I can see you.
We're new here.
We're just trying
to get to the roof.
Get a better look
at the place.
Believe me, it doesn't look
any better from up there.
Dad...
(moans)
It's going to
be okay, Danny.
What happened?
He was beaten up
by some ghosts.
My wife went to get help, but
there's only one doctor on duty
at the Processing Center.
Well, why don't you
let me take a look?
I know a little
bit about medicine.
Julian...
It can't hurt
to just look.
Hey.
I'm just going to take
a quick look here, okay?
Does that hurt?
(inhales sharply)
BASHIR: Here?
Well, looks like
you've been lucky.
No broken ribs, and these
cuts are mostly superficial.
You're going to be okay.
You're going to need
some clean rags
and something to
disinfect these wounds.
Alcohol should do.
I think I can get some.
Okay.
Here we go.
Looks like we
made a new friend.
FATHER: Hey!
You know, the district
could use another doctor.
I don't really
practice anymore.
But there are people
here who need you.
I'm sorry, but they'll have
to get along without me.
You two are new here
so let me explain
something to you.
You can forget about getting
out of here anytime soon.
This is your home now.
The only help we're going
to get is from each other
and if we don't start
pulling together
we're finished.
All we want is
to be left alone.
My mistake.
I thought you wanted
to get out of here.
We do.
Well, the only way
that's going to happen
is if we get organized,
and let people on the outside
know what's going on in here.
Do whatever you want.
Just leave us out of it.
If you want to be left alone...
that's fine with me.
But if you want to help us
and help yourselves
you know where to find me.
MAN: Our sea floor
mining project
is almost ready
to go into operation.
Now, the Pan-Caribbean
government did have
some misgivings, but I
think we've won them over.
I hear you just came
back from Christchurch.
Yes. Did a little
skiing on Mount Cook.
You're lucky. We had to cancel
our trip to the Alps this year
because of the student
protests in France.
I thought the Neo-Trotskyists
were going to put a stop
to that.
They're not having any more
luck than the Gaullists did.
Europe is falling apart.
Well, at least we don't
have to worry about that
kind of thing here.
Don't count on it.
You'll have to excuse
Jadzia's cynicism.
She was just mugged yesterday.
That kind of thing's bound
to give a negative impression
of the future.
So... who mugged you?
Did you see them?
It doesn't really matter.
I'm just glad that
I wasn't hurt.
Well, whoever it was
did a very thorough job.
They took everything
she had, even her I.D.
Chris rescued me and
let me use his computer
to get my replacement I.D.
You were lucky the police
didn't find you first.
If they'd caught you
on the street without I.D.
you might have ended up
in a Sanctuary District.
WOMAN: I thought they
stopped doing that.
MAN: Why would they?
It's the only way
to keep those people
off the streets.
Excuse us a minute.
- Is that true?
- Is what true?
About taking people without
I.D. to a Sanctuary District.
Yes, it is. Why?
I still haven't
found my friends.
And you think they might be
in a Sanctuary District?
It's possible.
If you hadn't found me,
I might have wound up in one.
Can we check and see
if they're inside?
Well, it might
take some doing.
The Sanctuary District records
are not posted on the Net.
But I might be able
to pull in some favors.
And I thought the lines
at the Replimat were bad.
(chuckles)
By the time we get dinner,
it'll be time for breakfast.
You'd think that before they
locked thousands of people
into a 20-square-block area,
they'd give some thought
as to how those people
were going to get fed.
I'm going to see how much
longer this is going to take.
Hey, Gimme!
I'm talking to you.
Let me see
your food card.
What for?
Because I said so.
Let him go!
What?
I said let him go!
Oh.
Well, when you
put it like that...
(clattering)
Leave them alone!
Are you all right?
(groaning)
Get his card!
Get his food card!
Come on, let's get out of here!
Come on. Let's go!
Help him!
He never would have gotten
hurt if it wasn't for us.
Breathe, damn you,
breathe!
God, he's gone.
(alarm blares)
Come on. We've got
to get out of here!
Cover!
They're gone.
For now, but they're
the least of our worries.
That man who just got
killed trying to help us--
that man was
Gabriel Bell.
Oh...
If only I'd had my medkit,
or even if I'd got
him to a hospital
I might have been
able to save him.
You did all you
could, Doctor.
But it wasn't
enough, was it?
A good man died because of us.
And what about the hostages?
What's going to happen to them?
Without Bell,
there's a good chance
those hostages are going to die.
And if that happens?
How is it going to affect
the future?
We have to save them.
Whatever it takes,
we have to make sure
those hostages survive.
(sighs)
All right, Chief.
Let's get over to
the transporter room
before we change our minds.
Too late, Major.
Looks like Starfleet's
changed our minds for us.
Headquarters thinks
our plan's too risky.
They're afraid that
while we're searching
for Sisko and the others
we may contaminate
the timeline.
Get me Admiral Wright.
I had a feeling you'd say that.
- That's odd.
- What is it?
I'm not getting any
response from Starfleet.
Is there something wrong
with our communications array?
I was just talking
to Starfleet Security
when my comm line went dead.
There's nothing
wrong at our end.
Everything
checks out fine.
Could be interference
on the comm channels.
Try a wide band
subspace signal.
Still nothing.
Maybe if I direct it toward
one of the Federation
communications satellites
in Earth orbit...
What is it, Chief?
They're not there.
The entire Earth
satellite network...
it's gone.
- The spacedocks,
the orbital habitats?
- All of it!
The Utopia Planitia
Yards on Mars,
the Terraforming
Stations on Venus,
Starfleet
Headquarters.
I'm not detecting a single sign
of Starfleet activity
anywhere in this sector.
Try a non-Federation
frequency.
The only subspace signals
I'm detecting are from
the vicinity of Alpha Centauri
and they're Romulan.
Well, that's impossible.
Do you think Sisko
and the others
might have somehow
altered the timeline?
They must've.
Then why weren't
we affected?
I'm not sure.
But maybe...
maybe when it exploded
the singularity that polarized
the chroniton particles
created some kind
of subspace bubble
around the ship--
isolated it from the
changes in the timeline.
I'm not sure,
but I'll have to run some tests.
One thing's
for certain.
Right now, this ship
is all that's left of Starfleet.
I thought you didn't want
to get involved.
We've changed
our minds.
Glad to hear it.
We can use all
the help we can get.
This place is about to explode.
Most of us agreed to live here
because they
promised us jobs.
I don't know about you,
but I haven't been on
any job interviews lately
and neither has anyone else.
They've forgotten about us.
So, what do we do?
We make them
remember.
Day after tomorrow
we're going to hold a rally
outside the Processing Center.
I want everyone to be there--
gimmes, ghosts,
even the dims.
I want to remind
the people outside
that we haven't
done anything wrong
that we're not criminals
and that we don't deserve
to live like this.
We'll spread the word.
Good.
One more thing.
Tell people when they
come to the rally
to bring their families,
their kids,
and try to look their best.
We're not derelicts
no matter what they say
about us.
I could probably use a shave.
Not to mention a bath.
Yes.
Yes, thank you.
You were right.
Your friends are in
Sanctuary District "A."
When can we get them out?
Well, it might
not be that easy.
The Sanctuary personnel
first have to find them.
And there's something like
10,000 people in there.
- Did they say how
long it would take?
- They're not sure.
But don't worry,
your friends are fine.
That's the whole point
of the Sanctuary--
to give people in trouble
food and a place to stay.
If that's all it's for
then why is there
a wall around it?
BASHIR: ...in two days, in
front of the Processing Center.
- Will you spread the word?
- MEN: All Right.
SISKO: Okay, you got it?
The day after tomorrow.
Try to be there, and tell
everyone else you know.
That's, uh, 500 people
we've talked to today.
That only leaves
about 9,000 to go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Slow down!
What's going on?
One of the guards
got in a fight
with a dim down,
down at Processing.
Now everyone's going crazy.
I have to find my dad.
(explosion)
(people yelling)
(alarm blaring)
(crowd shouting)
(grunting)
Give me that!
Get back!
(gunshot)
Get away!
Get away from him!
Come on, we have to get
him off the street!
(crowd yelling)
Everybody put your hands
on your head
and face the wall!
You can't do this.
I can do anything I want.
Now...
up against
the wall.
That's enough!
Well, look who we've got here.
Way to show initiative, new boy.
Take him, and throw
him back there
along with the rest
of our, uh, guests.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
I think I am making
a political statement.
Maybe if we're lucky I might
even be able to
stage a nice little,
uh, photo op.
I hope that meets
with your approval.
Do as he says.
Well, all right!
I've waited a long time
for this!
And I know I won't
be disappointed.
Ain't that right, new boy?
The name is Bell.
Gabriel Bell.