Jake!
Hi!
Leanne, I thought
you were on Bajor.
I came back early.
You know, I was just
thinking about you.
Really?
Yeah, I passed
the Klingon restaurant
where you and I and Orak
were eating dinner...
And you ordered the gagh.
Yeah. How is Orak?
I haven't talked
to him in a while.
We, uh, stopped seeing
each other a few weeks ago.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
So, are... you doing
anything tomorrow night?
Well, I'm supposed
to play dom-jot with Nog.
Oh.
But they're not
really firm plans.
In fact, I was thinking
of canceling them.
Really?
If you do cancel
would you be interested
in dinner?
Sure.
Great.
How about 1800
at the Klingon restaurant?
I'll be there.
But this time,
we'll skip the gagh.
Definitely.
I'll see you then.
Okay.
Move aside!
Look out!
Move! Move!
What have we got?
Bajoran transport coming in.
They had some kind
of accident on board.
They got casualties.
They're docking.
We should have
beamed the wounded
directly to the infirmary.
They have
a loose plasma coil.
We couldn't beam
through the radiation.
Docking clamps secure.
I'm opening the airlock.
Stand back.
Come on.
This way.
It's all right.
Here, I've got you.
Come along now.
Come on.
This way, Eminence.
Kai Winn.
The Vedek... take care
of the Vedek.
Odo to Kira.
Kira here.
I think you should meet us
in the Infirmary, Major.
Vedek Bareil
was on the transport.
He's been injured.
The report
from the transport, sir.
Give me the short version.
There was a molecular fracture
in one of the plasma conduits.
It was only a matter of time
before it gave way.
Once it collapsed
the entire relay
system exploded.
Was it sabotage?
I don't think so.
Why would you suspect sabotage?
I would prefer to discuss that
with the Emissary in private.
Put a pressor field
on that artery.
The arterial disruption
is too severe.
The pressor can't stop
the hemorrhaging.
All right, clamp off the artery
and then increase the
plasma level to maximum.
Cardiac arrest.
Clear.
He can't take
much more of that.
The arterial pressure
is falling.
I see it.
The neurotransmitter levels
are falling, too.
Two cc's cordrazine.
Doctor?
Do it.
Synaptic failure.
Apply direct neurostimulation
to the brain stem.
Thank you.
Vedek Bareil
and I were on our way
to a secret meeting
with a member
of the Cardassian
Central Command.
It was my intention
to open talks
between Bajor and Cardassia
that would lead to a treaty
and a final peace settlement.
You have been negotiating
peace with Cardassia?
The Prophets teach us
that while violence
may keep an enemy at bay
only peace
can make him a friend.
How long has this been going on?
Vedek Bareil has
been working to set up
this meeting with Legate Turrel
for the past five months.
They've discussed issues
ranging from war reparations
to the exchange of Ambassadors.
There's even the possibility
that the Cardassians
will issue a formal apology
for the pain and suffering
inflicted on the Bajoran people
during the occupation.
I was on my way to our first
face-to-face meeting
when we had the accident.
Please, don't take this
the wrong way
but I never would have guessed
that you would be the one
to bring such a bold vision
of peace to Bajor.
A large share of the credit
goes to Vedek Bareil.
Without him, the talks could
have never come this far.
It sounds like you've developed
a deeper appreciation
for Vedek Bareil.
I must admit, he has been
a loyal and trustworthy aide
since the election.
I'm not sure I could have been
as... forgiving
had I been in his place.
These talks
were Bareil's idea.
He's guided me through them
and without him, in the future,
these talks may never resume.
I'm sorry.
The radiation severely damaged
his neural pathways.
I did everything I could.
I know you did.
Did he ever regain
consciousness?
No, I don't think he suffered.
Thank you, Doctor.
I'm... on duty in Ops.
Excuse me.
Kira...
I think they can get along
without you in Ops today.
Maybe, but I need to be there.
I appreciate your concern
but I'll grieve in my own way,
in my own time.
We're ready to begin
the autopsy, Doctor.
Release the stasis field.
Let's begin with a neural scan.
I want to map
his central axonal pathways.
Find out where
the breakdown began.
Shall I begin taking
neural tissue samples?
Looks like the damage began
in the parietal lobe.
Spread through the rest of the
brain in a retrograde manner.
Wait a minute.
A neuron just fired
in his cerebral cortex.
There it is again.
His nerves, his nerves
are still transmitting
electrical impulses
to his brain.
How can that be?
His brain activity is zero.
His nervous system
should be completely inactive.
I don't know,
but it means his body's
still capable of sending
messages to the brain
even though the brain
can't process them.
The radiation he was exposed to
might have fortified
his peripheral cell membranes.
If we can regenerate
his pathways
with his own neuron cells,
we might be able to revive him.
What about brain damage?
There's been no oxygen to his
brain for almost 40 minutes.
But he's been in stasis
for most of that time.
That, combined
with the strengthening
of his cell membranes might
buy us the time we need.
We'll have to direct a burst
of electrical energy
into his cerebral cortex.
If the burst is
the proper intensity
it should create a cascade
effect within the brain
and the neurons might resume
their normal firing pattern.
Okay.
Let's close up
the cranial cavity.
The neurogenic stimulator
is in place.
Let's try a 50-millivolt burst.
Increase it to 60.
Seventy.
That's five millivolts above
what normal tissue can stand.
It'll burn out
his cerebral cortex.
If I'm right,
the inaprovaline drug
that I gave him should
provide additional resistance
against the excess
electrostimulation.
Seventy!
Doctor!
Well, it's
a little early to tell
but I'm hoping
he'll make a full recovery.
He should be back on his feet
again in a few weeks.
You say that so calmly.
But it's not every doctor
that can lose a patient,
and then have him
back on his feet
in a few weeks.
Indeed, you are too modest.
You've performed nothing
less than a miracle here.
The Prophets must walk
with you, Doctor.
Well, I and the Prophets
were lucky
that the ionizing radiation
left a residual signature
on Bareil's axonal pathways.
That's what really
made this possible.
Whoever deserves the credit,
Doctor, I am grateful.
And I am grateful
you were not taken from us,
Vedek Bareil.
My work here
is not yet finished.
No...
it is not.
We must resume
the negotiations immediately.
We can't risk losing
the momentum we've established.
I would like to send
a coded message
to Legate Turrel,
and invite him to come to DS9
to continue the talks.
Wait a minute.
Bareil's in no condition
to conduct negotiations.
Bareil will simply
be advising me.
I will conduct the actual talks.
Then I'll allow it as long
as your visits don't tire him.
Agreed.
Vedek, we will talk again soon.
Eminence.
So...
are we going to be playing
springball next month?
You bet, although I'm afraid I
might have an unfair advantage.
You mean, playing
against a dead man?
No.
I've been practicing.
My dad said that you
were looking for me.
Yeah, um, it's
about tomorrow night.
Don't worry.
I've all ready
taken care of that.
I met these three Terrellians
who were bragging about
how great they are at dom-jot.
So I arranged a game...
us against them.
Look, Nog, we have
a-a little problem.
No, we don't.
I guarantee we'll beat them.
It's not that.
I just can't make it
tomorrow night.
But it has to be
tomorrow night...
they're leaving the next day.
I-I made other plans.
What could be more
important than dom-jot?
I have a date.
Oh, well, that's different.
It is?
Yeah. Money is money
but women are better.
Is that a Rule of Acquisition?
It's a personal rule.
So, who is she?
Leanne.
Ah, Leanne!
Ah!
Way to go, Jake!
So, what is the name of my date?
I hope she's as cute as Leanne.
Your date?
She has a friend, right?
I'm sure she does.
Then tell her
to bring her along.
Nog, that's not
what I had in mind.
That's because
you were confused.
Would you rather
the three of us go out?
When you put it that way...
Exactly.
Just one thing, Jake.
You're still pretty new
at this dating business.
Just promise me you won't
do anything to embarrass me.
I'll do my best.
Ah, this'll be great.
Maybe I'll even wash my lobes.
I suggest we put off discussion
of the Cardassians
returning the Orbs
until diplomatic relations
have been established.
That would only delay
an inevitable argument.
But it will give the peace
process a chance to grow.
Once the Cardassians
are invested in the process
it, it may be easier
to discuss these matters.
Very well.
A wise decision, Eminence.
I hope so, Vedek Bareil.
The first meeting with Turrel
is scheduled
for tomorrow afternoon.
I will see you before then.
I take it you're not here
to deliver a good report,
Doctor.
In order to revive you...
I had to flood
your nervous system
with neurogenic radiation.
Unfortunately, this has caused
some kind of selective
vasoconstriction
of your arteries.
The result is
an inadequate blood flow
to your internal organs.
So what do we do?
We'd like to place you back
into stasis...
do some research
on your condition.
For how long?
I don't know yet.
Days, weeks...
even months.
Maybe even years?
Maybe.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
that's not acceptable.
I can't allow myself
to be put in storage
when my people need me.
I don't want to wake
to a Bajor still haunted
by the memory of the occupation.
I realize how important
these talks are to Bajor
but, as your physician,
my duty is to you first.
And I have a duty to Bajor.
Please, help me heal my people.
It's the only thing
that matters to me.
There is...
an experimental drug...
called vasokin
which would increase
the blood flow to your organs
and might... enable you
to function normally
for a while.
But there is a great
deal of risk attached.
What sort of risk?
In 22 percent of cases,
vasokin has severely damaged
patients' lungs,
kidneys, even heart...
sometimes the brain.
In your condition,
it could be fatal.
But it would allow me
to function normally
for the next few days?
Yes.
But why risk your life
for a few days?
I have no great desire to die,
Doctor
but I am determined to carry out
the will of the Prophets
as long as I am able
and I cannot
carry out their will
if I am unconscious
in some stasis tube.
Please...
begin the vasokin treatments.
All right.
We'll start this afternoon.
I only hope
we don't regret this.
So do I.
Station Log, Stardate 48498.4.
Legate Turrel
has arrived aboard the station
to resume the negotiations.
Vedek Bareil suggested
that I sit in on the talks
as an impartial observer
and Kai Winn has agreed.
Perhaps you didn't hear me.
There are no Bajoran prisoners
left in Cardassian hands.
Maybe we should redefine
our terms.
Perhaps there are
no official prisoners
but are there a number
of, shall we say...
detainees?
There are of course people being
detained at the Justice Ministry
for crimes against the state
but that is a discussion
for another time.
Now, I would like to discuss
what you've called
"war reparations."
We would be willing to pay
for the destruction
of all Bajoran property
incurred during our occupation
as long as you would be
willing to return to us
all Cardassian
property and equipment
left behind on Bajor.
What... sort of property?
I can provide you with lists
of material, equipment...
as long as we have
an agreement in principle
that anything
of Cardassian origin
does still belong
to the Cardassian people.
I... will consider your offer.
Good.
Shall we take a recess?
He's up to something.
That much seems clear.
But what?
Why is he insisting on
this principle of his?
I need Bareil.
He's the only one who knows
the entire negotiating record.
Bareil has been talking
with Turrel for months.
He understands him...
respects him...
I think he even likes him.
I'm afraid you may have
to face the possibility
that Bareil may not be able
to help you much longer.
I was chosen by the Prophets
to lead our people
into a new era.
I know that!
But I was not meant
to be in a room
with a Cardassian
debating legalisms
and diplomatic nuances.
I can't do this without Bareil.
If he dies...
then peace with Cardassia
dies with him.
My father used to take me
to the wilderness preserves
on Vulcan.
So for years
I thought that's what
their planet was like...
animals and plants everywhere.
I had no idea there
were people on Vulcan.
Boy, Jake, she talks
a lot for a female.
Excuse me!
Riska, weren't you telling me
your uncle runs a bar
on Osinar VI?
You know, Nog's uncle
runs this bar.
Is that right?
Let's not make
foolish conversation.
Just sit there
and look beautiful.
Nog, what do you
think you're doing?
I think I know
how to handle females.
Jake, you know,
I've been thinking...
after we're done eating
we could take the females
to the holosuites.
I've borrowed one of my
uncle's private programs.
"The massacre on Ferris VI."
We could spend an hour
pillaging and looting
the frightened townspeople.
I don't think so.
No one's asking you
to think, my dear.
Here, make yourself useful.
Cut up my food for me.
You must be joking.
She's so dumb!
She's perfect!
That's it.
Wait.
You're not leaving?
I suppose you want me
to sit here
and cut your food for you, too?
I never said anything
about cutting...
I hope you and your friend
enjoy your holosuite.
Come on.
Nog!
Don't say another word, Jake.
I think you've done enough
damage for one night!
Me?!
Yeah, you...
you were treating
my female
as if she was an equal!
And you were behaving
like an idiot.
This is the last time
I'll ever do a favor for you.
From now on,
you get your own dates.
And you can find someone else
to play dom-jot with!
Fine!
Good!
Turrel... is trying to get
a concession from you
that I already rejected.
Tell him...
that the question
of Cardassian
property on Bajor
was already dealt with...
in the armistice talks
four years ago.
I...
Don't... don't worry.
He'll... he'll still
pay the reparations.
What about this question
of mining rights?
His attention is wandering.
He's in pain.
Give him more of the drug.
He's had enough.
Then you'll need to give
him something else.
The negotiations
resume in less than six hours
and we still have 40 pages!
Listen to me.
I don't care
about your negotiations
and I don't care
about your treaty.
All I care about
is my patient
and at the moment, he needs more
treatment and less politics.
Now, you can either
leave here willingly
or I'll call Security
and have you thrown out.
You won't need to call them.
I'll do it myself.
Put yourself in the hands
of the Prophets, Bareil.
They will not forsake you.
Yes, Eminence.
Is there anything I can do?
Just be here.
I'm beginning to dislike
seeing that look
on your face, Doctor.
As I feared
the vasokin has already
damaged your internal organs.
What happens now?
I can replace the damaged organs
with artificial implants
but as long
as you're taking the drug
I can't guarantee
that the damage
won't spread.
I think you
should reconsider
letting me put you in stasis.
I'm afraid my mind's made up.
Just get me through
the negotiations.
I must carry out
the will of the Prophets.
Please...
whatever it takes...
just do it.
Are you going to call Security
and have me removed
from this room now, Doctor?
It hadn't occurred
to me... yet.
How is Bareil?
The organ replacement
surgery went well.
He's still unconscious
but he should be awake
within the hour.
Oh, good.
There are still several points
I have to discuss with him
before the next
negotiating session.
That's why I'm here.
When you see Bareil
I want you to tell him
that you don't need him.
That you can complete these
negotiations without him.
But I do need him, Doctor.
I realize that.
But I want you to tell him
that you don't.
You seem to be
asking me to lie.
I'm asking you to free Bareil
of his obligations to you.
The only way
he'll accept that
is if you tell him
he's no longer needed...
that you can go on without him.
Now, if that's a lie,
then so be it.
That doesn't sound
like a... Starfleet officer.
I'm a doctor first.
And right now, I'm trying
to give my patient
his best chance to live.
The only way to do that
is to put him in stasis.
Bareil knows that
but his desire to complete
these negotiations is so strong
that he's forcing me to keep him
conscious and mentally alert
even though it may kill him.
None of us wants that
to happen, Doctor.
But, if I'm not mistaken
the decision regarding
Bareil's treatment is up to him.
Yes.
As the patient, it is his right
to make that choice
but I am asking you
to help me change his mind.
Eminence...
you're the Kai.
These are your negotiations.
Let this be
your moment in history.
Finish the talks on your own
and you won't have to share
the credit with anyone.
You say that as though success
is guaranteed.
Of course...
if the talks fail, you'll need
someone to accept the blame...
a scapegoat.
You're a coward.
You're afraid to stand alone.
Bareil's already made
his decision, Doctor.
I won't interfere.
And, Doctor...
I won't forget
what you've said here.
Neither will I.
So, you never told me
about your double date.
Not much to tell.
That's not what I hear.
Quark tells me that you
and Nog aren't speaking
to each other.
You should have seen
the way he acted, Dad.
He was acting
like a spoiled brat.
I've never been so embarrassed.
I don't think Leanne
will ever speak to me again.
Hmm, so what did he do?
All kinds of stupid things.
Riska couldn't even
say two words
without him telling her
to be quiet.
And he insisted that she cut up
his food for him.
He was treating her
like she was some kind of slave.
It sounds like he's acting
like a Ferengi to me.
You can't blame him for that.
Well, in that case, maybe
you were right all along.
About what?
You once said
that humans and Ferengis
are too different
to ever really be friends.
I remember saying that,
and you know what?
I was wrong.
You and Nog proved that.
Sure, you have
your cultural differences
but there's a real bond
between you.
Well, I know one thing.
I'm never going to set him up
on a date again.
I think the two of you
should talk this over
before it becomes
too big a problem.
I'm not sure Nog is going to be
willing to talk to me so soon.
Well, I guess you'll have to do
something to get his attention.
What happened?
I don't know.
Two cc's morphenolog.
It's all right.
You're getting help.
I thought I made it clear
there were to be no visitors
for the next three hours!
It's not her fault, Doctor.
Bareil called me himself.
He said he had some ideas
on the treaty.
And you just couldn't wait
to hear them, could you?
His left temporal lobe
is showing signs
of massive synaptic failure.
Well, I hope you got
all the advice
you needed, Eminence
because the vasokin
has damaged his brain
and that damage is irreversible.
Will he regain consciousness?
Not in his present condition.
You were able to replace
some of his internal organs
with artificial implants.
Could you do something similar
with the damaged
parts of his brain?
It's hard to say
with any certainty.
There's still a great deal
about the way the brain operates
we don't understand.
One of my professors
at medical school used to say
that the brain has a "spark of
life" that can't be replicated.
If we begin to replace
parts of Bareil's brain
with artificial implants,
that spark may be lost.
But you're saying,
if you don't do it
Bareil will never regain
consciousness and he'll die.
I think we should
consider what Bareil
would want us to do.
Bareil wanted
these negotiations
to be completed
no matter what the cost.
With all due respect,
Your Eminence
you're hardly
an impartial observer here.
You have a personal interest
in these talks.
There is more at stake
than one man's life.
One man's life is all I'm
concerned with at the moment.
I think she's right, Julian.
I think Bareil would want
the positronic implants.
Kira, if I go through with this
the man who wakes up may not be
the man you used to know.
I realize that... but I know
how important this is to him
and I know he wouldn't want
to just be put
in stasis indefinitely
waiting for some medical
solution that may never come.
Do the surgery, Julian.
Let him finish what he started.
Mr. Sisko?
Odo, I'd like you
to do me a favor.
Hmm?
I want to be arrested.
This is outrageous!
I didn't steal anything
from the Tholian Ambassador!
Just another innocent man
arrested for a crime
he didn't commit.
What is he doing here?
As if you didn't know.
Your accomplice here
has also denied involvement
but I have an eyewitness
who saw both of you
breaking
into the Tholian Ambassador's
quarters last night.
I don't even know
what a Tholian looks like!
Tell it to the magistrate.
At least put me in my own cell!
I'm sorry the quarters
aren't to your liking.
Please feel free to submit
a complaint to the management.
The positronic implant
is functioning normally.
And the midbrain interface
is on line and he's awake.
Bareil.
Yes, Major?
How are you feeling?
Awake.
Everything is different.
Different?
In what way?
It's hard to explain...
but when you touch me
it doesn't seem real.
It's more like
the distant memory of a touch.
Vedek, do you remember
the negotiations?
I have some questions for you.
Of course, Eminence.
I will do all that I can.
Something's wrong.
No kidding.
That's not what I mean.
My father told me that if I
got caught stealing again
he would send me back
to live on the Ferengi homeworld
with my grandmother.
So where is he?
I mean, why isn't he here
yelling and threatening me?
And where's Uncle Quark?
Now, I'm late for work.
And come to think of it,
what are you doing here?
Ask Odo.
No, no, no,
throwing you in here
wasn't Odo's idea.
You don't just arrest
the Station Commander's son
without some
really strong evidence.
And I know there
is no evidence
because I know
we didn't do anything.
So why are we in here, Jake?
All right,
I put Odo up to this
because I wanted
to talk to you.
In here?
I didn't think you'd
listen to me otherwise.
Well, this better be good.
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
I guess I just forgot
you were a Ferengi.
You forgot?
To most people, the lobes
are a dead giveaway.
What I mean is,
we spend so much time together
and we seem so much alike
I, I sometimes forget
we're different.
I know we're different.
I mean, anyone
who talks to a female
with fawning respect
is no Ferengi.
It made me sick.
You want to talk about sick?
Sick is making Riska
cut up your food for you.
Well, at least I didn't
have her chew it.
Chew it!
That's right.
In traditional Ferengi homes
the females soften the food
with their teeth
before they give it
to the males.
That is disgusting.
I knew you would react that way
which is why I did
not have her do it.
Well, do you have
any other disgusting
Ferengi customs
I should know about?
Plenty.
And I know plenty of human
customs which disgust me.
Great, so we both
disgust each other.
You know, as we get older
this is just going
to get worse.
But I know one thing
I don't want to lose you
as a friend.
Well, in that case
double-dating is definitely out.
Agreed.
And I guess
we'll just have to deal
with the rest
of our disgusting habits
as they come up.
I guess so.
You feel better?
Yeah.
Good.
Now can we get out of here?
Sure.
Odo?
Odo.
He-He's just playing around.
- Odo?
- Odo!
Station Log, supplemental.
Kai Winn has announced
that Legate Turrel has signed
the peace treaty.
The news has sent a shock wave
throughout the quadrant.
And although there is
still some opposition
from hard-line elements
on both Bajor and Cardassia
it looks as though
they are finally willing
to put their long conflict
behind them.
Remind me not to invite
you to my next party.
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm sort of casting
a pall over this gathering.
Julian, no one's expecting you
to provide entertainment
but you should try
to enjoy yourself.
After all, the celebration
is for you, too.
Well, frankly, I can't imagine
what I've done...
deserves a celebration.
You kept him alive
against incredible odds.
No matter what happens
you should always
be proud of that.
Excuse me.
Your Eminence.
Yes?
Kai Winn, allow me
to introduce "Kai Winn."
I don't understand.
In honor of the occasion
I've named my latest creation
after you.
It's a chocolate soufflé with...
Haligian tongue sauce.
Well, I'm very honored.
Mmm... mmm.
And you're also very popular.
Believe me, I can't keep up
with the orders so far!
Medical emergency.
Dr. Bashir to the Infirmary.
Please excuse me.
It's the other half
of his brain, isn't it?
But you can still help him,
can't you?
You can replace
the other half of his brain
with a positronic matrix.
I'm sorry, Nerys,
but this is where it ends.
What do you mean?
I won't remove whatever
last shred of humanity
Bareil has left.
But you can do it.
Perhaps, child
it is time to listen
to Dr. Bashir.
Sure. You got your peace treaty,
your place in history.
You don't need Bareil anymore.
Believe me, child,
I share your pain
but I think the Prophets
are calling to Bareil.
I will see to it that
Bajor never forgets him.
Doctor.
Julian... you can't give up now.
You have to keep going.
Nerys...
if I remove
the rest of his brain
and replace it with a machine
he may look like Bareil,
he may even talk like Bareil
but he won't be Bareil.
That "spark of life"
will be gone.
He'll be dead.
And I'll be the one
who killed him.
But if we do nothing, he'll die.
That's right, he will.
But he'll die like a man,
not a machine.
Please...
don't make me
fight you on this one.
Just let him go.
How much time?
All brain activity should cease
within the next three hours.
I'd like to stay
with him till then.
Of course.
You got your peace treaty.
I just wish
that we'd had more time for us.
There's so much
I never told you, but...
this is the time we have left,
so I'd better say it now.
I'll... I'll never forget
the first time I saw you
the day you came to the station.
You had...
such a serenity about you.
I thought you had
all the answers.
It really got on my nerves
for a while.
Then I got to know you
and I... realized you were just
as confused as the rest of us.
You just accepted your confusion
better than anyone
I've ever known.
That's when I realized
I loved you.