KIRA: First Officer's Log,
Stardate 48521.5.
Odo and I are returning
to Deep Space 9
after reviewing security
procedures at Prophet's
Landing
the Bajoran colony closest
to the Cardassian border.
Those orbital
sensor platforms
should give the colonists
plenty of advance warning
in case the Cardassians
ever decide
to violate
the new treaty.
Hopefully.
How did your meeting
with Security
Chief Bemar go?
Fine.
Was he properly
impressed
by the depth
of your expertise?
( disdainful snort )
Odo, is something bothering you?
What makes you say that?
Well, for one thing, you
haven't said five words to me
since we left Prophet's Landing.
Huh!
Look, if I've
done something
to offend you,
I wish you'd tell me what it is.
It's not important.
Whatever you say.
Certainly not worth
making an issue about.
Well, glad to hear it.
It's just...
When Governor Avesta
invited us to dinner
at his house...
Go on.
You said no.
And?
You never bothered to ask me
if I wanted to go.
You wanted to go to the
Governor's house for dinner?
Not particularly.
Well, then, what's the problem?
The problem is you never asked
what I wanted.
Odo, you don't eat.
Besides, you hate socializing
with people you don't know.
Well, that's beside the point.
I would have liked to have
been consulted, that's all.
You're right.
Next time we are invited
out for dinner
I will make sure you
are the one
to say no.
I'd appreciate that.
( console beeping )
Hold on.
I'm picking up
a wide band
subspace transmission from
a Lissepian supply ship.
They've just been attacked
by a Maquis interceptor.
Long-range sensors
are detecting
a modified Peregrine-class
courier ship
likely armed, one-man crew,
bearing 268 mark 301.
The Maquis use
Peregrine-class courier ships.
KIRA: The Lissepians
didn't sustain
any serious damage.
I'm going after him.
Right.
I don't know what
the Maquis have done
to that ship's engines,
but it's fast.
Not fast enough.
We're closing on him.
We better
catch him soon.
We're entering
the Badlands.
Wait a minute, I've lost him.
The Badlands' plasma fields
are disrupting
our sensors.
Increase the sensor bandwidth.
That should compensate
for the interference.
I hope you're right.
KIRA: Well, he can't
have gotten far.
He's got to be somewhere
in this solar system.
ODO: There he is.
Looks like
he's trying to land
on one of the moons
orbiting that gas giant.
I'm following him in.
There's something wrong
with his ship.
It looks like his attitude
stabilizers have failed.
Can you get
a transporter lock on him?
ODO: Too much
interference.
He's trying to land
on that moon.
Ah, we've lost him.
Did he make it?
ODO: I don't know.
Something in
the moon's atmosphere
is jamming our sensors.
Then I guess we'll have to land
and see for ourselves.
O'BRIEN: O'Brien to Sisko.
Go ahead.
Commander, there's
someone here to see you.
SISKO: Who is it?
It's Nog.
Nog?
Tell him it's urgent.
He says it's urgent.
Send him in.
I told you he'd see me.
( chuckles )
Commander...
first, let me express
my most sincere thanks
for allowing me
to speak with you.
You're welcome.
Now... what is this
all about?
I wanted to
give you... this.
Open it.
What's this?
It's latinum.
I know it's latinum, but why
are you giving it to me?
Yesterday, I completed
the Ferengi
Attainment Ceremony.
I'm an adult.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
But...
that doesn't explain this.
According to Ferengi Bylaws
section 105, subparagraph ten,
upon reaching adulthood
Ferengi males must purchase
an apprenticeship
from a suitable
role model.
I choose you.
You want to be my apprentice?
That's right.
I want to be the first Ferengi
in Starfleet.
Now, who do I see
about getting a uniform?
Nog, if you want to become
a Starfleet officer
you have to attend the Academy.
All right.
Where do I sign up?
It's not that simple.
As a non-Federation citizen
you need a letter of reference
from a command-level officer
before you can even take
the entrance exam.
A command-level officer...
you mean, like you.
Well, yes... like me.
Then you'll write the letter.
I'll think about it.
Thank you, Commander.
I know you'll make
the right decision.
Aren't you forgetting
something?
Keep it.
Consider it a token
of my appreciation.
( sighs )
ODO:
Tricorders are useless.
The atmospheric ionization
is jamming their transponders.
KIRA: Are you sure he's
in these caverns?
Well, he wasn't in the
wreckage of his ship
and given the weather
conditions on the surface
there's no way anyone
could survive out there
for very long,
so that leaves...
( rumbling )
That's the third quake
since we got here.
This moon must be
seismically unstable.
The sooner we find our fugitive,
the better off we'll be.
Well, finding him
isn't going to be easy.
These caverns
could go on forever.
And with all this
seismic activity
I don't want to stay here
any longer than we have to.
I say we split up.
We meet back here
in 20 minutes
and if we haven't
found him by then
we may have to leave
without him.
If he's smart,
he'll let us find him.
Federation prison
would be paradise
compared to this place.
Well, let's hope
he's smart.
I'll see you
in 20 minutes.
KIRA: Kira to Odo.
Odo, can you hear me?
This is Odo.
I can barely hear you.
Odo, I'm trapped.
I need your help.
Come quickly.
Odo, do you read me?
Stay where you are, Major.
I'm on my way.
KIRA:
Odo, is that you?
I'm right here, Major.
Odo, I'm glad
to see you.
What's wrong?
You're not going to believe
this-- my foot is stuck.
Stuck? How?
I don't know.
I must have stepped
in a fissure or something.
I can't get it loose.
Let me take a look.
It's not a fissure.
Then what is it?
Your foot's
been encased
in some kind of crystal.
And from the look of things...
the crystal is spreading.
( rumbling )
ODO: Now, you're sure
you can't pull it loose?
KIRA: Oh, believe me,
I've tried.
Maybe if you
slip your foot
out of your boot?
I can barely feel
my foot, the crystal is
pressing against it so hard.
There's no way
I can get my boot off.
Hold on a minute.
This might
hurt a bit.
Go ahead.
( grunts )
( chuckles )
I fail to see the humor
in this situation.
Come on, Odo.
It's pretty ridiculous,
don't you think
the two of us being outsmarted
by a chunk of crystal?
Well, I'm not giving up
just yet.
Neither am I.
Hand me my phaser.
You sure this
is a good idea?
If you're not careful...
I may blow off my foot
and give Julian
the chance to prove
what a wonderful doctor he is?
Don't worry, I have
no intention of giving him
the opportunity.
Stand back.
I guess that wasn't
such a good idea after all.
The crystal formation
seems to have somehow
fed off the energy
from your phaser.
( loud rumbling )
Odo to Mekong.
Two to beam out.
Energize.
Odo to Mekong.
( sighs )
I can't contact
the runabout.
There's too much
interference.
I'll have to walk back
to the landing site
and try to transport
you from there.
Are you worried
about leaving me here?
Now that you mention it, yes.
I'll be fine, Odo.
I promise not to go anywhere.
Nog, hand me that
phase matrix recalibrator.
Here you are,
Father.
QUARK:
Is it fixed yet?
Not yet, Brother.
What's taking
so long?
We're working
as fast as we can.
The replicators'
entire power supply grid
has been shorted out.
I told you, Brother,
if you don't shut down
your replicators at least once
a week for routine maintenance
you risk system overloads
like this one.
You said it might
overload the system, might.
NOG: He tried to warn you,
Uncle Quark.
You should have
listened to him.
No, it's my fault.
I should have
explained it better.
Of course it's your fault.
Everything that goes wrong
here is your fault.
It says so
in your contract.
Now, this mess had better be
cleaned up before lunchtime
or I'm taking the losses
out of your pay.
Of course, Brother.
Um... I need to get
a replacement power coupling
from the storage room.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Nog, what's going on?
If you're here
to order lunch
you'll have to come
back in an hour.
Actually, I just ate.
Hey, that was
a pretty funny joke
you pulled on my dad
this morning.
What?
You know-- about wanting
to join Starfleet.
I wasn't joking.
Come on, Nog.
You don't really expect me
to fall for that one.
Did you tell your
father I was joking?
Yeah. Kind of.
How could you do that to me?
I want you
to go back to your father
and tell him
that you were wrong.
All right, calm down.
I mean, how was I supposed
to know you were serious?
You never said you wanted
to join Starfleet before.
I'm saying it now.
So what brought this on?
I have my reasons.
Okay, name one.
Why should I?
Because I'm your friend
and friends don't keep secrets
from one another.
It's not a secret.
I just don't feel
like talking about it.
Why?
Because it's personal.
Now, stop asking me.
All right, but my father's
a pretty smart guy
and if this is
some kind of trick
he's going
to figure it out.
There's nothing to figure out.
I'm joining Starfleet,
and that's that.
Now, if you don't mind,
I have a lot of work to do.
Computer, lock onto
these coordinates
and initiate transport sequence.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Explain.
The high level of
atmospheric ionization
is inhibiting transporter lock.
Can you compensate
for the interference
by using pattern enhancers?
Negative.
Pattern enhancers
will not function
in a polarized
ionization field.
Is there any way to achieve
a transporter lock
in this kind
of ionization field?
Negative.
( Odo groans )
Computer, send out
a priority one distress signal
to Deep Space 9.
Unable to comply.
Communication systems
are inoperable
due to atmospheric
interference.
In that case,
launch a communications probe
and instruct it to begin
a continuous broadcast
of our whereabouts
as soon as it clears
the atmosphere.
Working.
( probe thrusters )
Probe launch confirmed.
Computer, given ideal conditions
how soon can we expect help
from Deep Space 9?
Deep Space 9 should receive
the probe's distress signal
in approximately two days.
( Odo sighs )
( phaser fire )
Kira! I heard
phaser fire.
You just missed
our friend.
He came out of
that tunnel.
I think he was as
surprised as I was.
He fired at me
from over there
and when I shot back, he
ran off down the tunnel.
Don't worry.
His aim wasn't any
better than mine was.
He didn't
miss by much.
My lucky day.
I see you've put in
a request to reassign
Ensign Vilix'pran
from cargo inspection.
I think that
would be best.
Given his condition,
I don't want him
coming into contact
with any hazardous materials.
His condition?
Vilix'pran is budding.
His buds are undergoing
individuation
in just over a month.
You mean,
he's pregnant.
Twins.
SISKO: Ah.
Reassignment granted.
I'll have to make sure
I offer my congratulations
to the Ensign the
next time I see him.
Well, O'Brien and I
are throwing him
a baby shower
in a couple of days.
I think it would mean a lot
to him if you were there.
Are you getting
him anything?
O'Brien's building him
a hatchling pond
and I've put an order
in with Garak
for some new baby clothes.
Count me in.
Aye, sir.
Ensign Pran... hmm.
Commander Sisko, have
you made up your mind yet
about my letter?
Not exactly.
What does that mean,
"not exactly"?
Look, Nog, I have
to be honest with you.
When I think of candidates
for Starfleet Academy
yours is not the first name
that comes to mind.
Why not? Because
I'm a Ferengi?
Not at all.
The fact is, your reputation
on this station
leaves a lot to be desired.
Your school grades
are mediocre at best
and you've had more
than a few run-ins
with Constable Odo.
Okay, okay, so I've
made some mistakes.
I admit that.
But I could do better.
Just give me a chance.
You wanted
to see me, Benjamin?
Lieutenant, I need
a complete inventory
of the contents
of Cargo Bay 12.
Didn't we inventory
12 last week?
I'd like it done again.
All right, I'll assign
a crew to it immediately.
Actually, I already have
someone in mind
for the job.
Really? Who?
Nog.
He's asked for
a recommendation
to Starfleet Academy.
Nog?
My reaction exactly.
I always thought
it would be interesting
to have a Ferengi
in Starfleet... but Nog?
I know it seems unlikely
but before I
make up my mind
I want to give him
a chance to prove himself.
Commander, there's
a lot of valuable equipment
in Cargo Bay 12.
I know.
Maybe I should assign
a couple of crew members
to assist him.
No, I want him
to do it alone--
no help, no interference
no one looking
over his shoulder.
( deep sigh )
I wish I could
analyze this material.
Too bad our tricorders
don't work.
Or our communicators
or the transporter.
Our fugitive
couldn't have chosen
a better place to hide.
Very convenient,
don't you think?
You make it sound like
he planned on trapping us.
Well, maybe he did,
but it's not going to work.
I'm going to get you
out of here.
How long do you think
I have, Odo?
Long enough.
I figure at the rate
the crystal's been growing...
I'm going to be
completely covered
in less than 12 hours.
Unless this cave
collapses first.
There has got to be a way
to shatter this crystal!
I'm sure there is,
but that doesn't mean
we're going to find it
in less than 12 hours!
We'll find it.
Major...
do you ever look
at the criminal activity reports
we get
from Starfleet Security?
Not often.
Well, you should.
They make
fascinating reading.
A few months ago,
we got a report
on a theft on Remmil VI.
It seems the natives
there spin a kind
of crystalline webbing
that they use
to construct
their buildings.
A band of
Nausicaan raiders
broke into their
Central Museum
by using a high-frequency
ultrasonic generator
to create a sympathetic
vibration inside the webbing
and shatter it.
So all we need to do
is find a band
of Nausicaan raiders
and ask them to give us a hand?
No, I might be able to put
together a makeshift generator
using the covariant oscillator
on the runabout.
Ah, the trick will be
finding the right
frequency to create
a sympathetic vibration
inside this crystal.
I'm going to have
to go back to the runabout
start assembling the generator.
Keep your phaser handy in case
our friend decides
to come back.
I will.
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
Constable...
when we get
back to the station
I'm going to
start reading
those criminal
activity reports.
I'll make sure
you get them.
DAX:
Due to a computer error
we lost the manifest
on this entire cargo bay.
Commander Sisko
would like you
to re-inventory
its contents.
The entire cargo bay?
That's right.
By myself?
Look, Nog,
Starfleet isn't just
about diplomacy,
exploration.
A lot of the time,
it's just hard work.
When does Commander
Sisko want it done?
He would like
the manifest on his desk
first thing
in the morning.
He'll have it tonight
before he goes off duty.
Tomorrow morning
will be fine, Nog.
Now, if you don't
mind, Lieutenant
I'd like
to get started.
How long do you think
it's going to be
before the generator
finds the right frequency?
It's hard to say.
It could take hours.
I don't suppose there's
any way to speed things up.
I didn't think so.
Don't worry, Major.
I have every intention of
getting us back to the station
by tomorrow night.
Chief O'Brien is counting on it.
What does O'Brien
have to do with it?
We... have an appointment.
What kind of appointment?
Talk to me, Odo.
It helps pass the time.
The, uh, Chief and I
are supposed to go
kayaking together
in a holosuite.
You're kidding.
How did he talk you
into that one?
He didn't "talk me"
into anything.
It's really quite enjoyable.
You mean, you've done it before?
Twice.
He invited me
one evening
and seeing I had
no plans, I accepted.
I'm sorry. I'm just
having trouble
imagining the two of you
together in a boat.
Well, if it helps any
he's the one who
does all the singing.
He sings?
He says it's necessary
to establish
a smooth paddling rhythm.
This gets
better and better.
What kinds of songs
does he sing?
Ancient human
sea chanteys, mostly.
He's particularly fond
of one called "Louie, Louie."
I never pictured O'Brien
as the nautical type.
Next to his work
and his family
shooting the rapids is
his favorite activity.
He's had the holo-program
since he was on the Enterprise.
How long do these
boat trips usually take?
That depends.
On what?
On how many times
we capsize.
It must be a very
difficult program.
It's extremely difficult.
According to him
he's dislocated
his shoulder
half a dozen times
trying to make it
down those rapids.
Then why does
he keep doing it?
Because he loves it.
And it's been
my observation
that you humanoids
have a hard time
giving up
the things you love
no matter how much
they might hurt you.
I'm glad you're here, Odo.
I'm glad I'm here, too.
Odo!
( rocks thudding )
Major...
I'm all right.
What about the generator?
It's fine.
It still hasn't found
the right frequency
to shatter the crystal.
Tell it to hurry.
A couple more tremors
like that last one
and this whole cave is
going to collapse.
Well, we'll just
have to make sure
that doesn't happen.
After all, we've been
in worse situations
than this one
and come out all right.
Name three.
I can't think of any, either.
No, it... it's not that.
It's just that...
that wasn't
the response I expected.
What do you mean?
In the
detective novels
Chief O'Brien
gives me to read
when the hero says
"We've been in tougher
situations than this one"
his friends
always agree.
I never read
any of those books.
Well, there must be
some humanoid platitude
I can use to cheer you up.
I don't have
much use
for platitudes, Odo.
I'd rather face the truth
of a situation
and go on
from there.
I feel the same way.
I know you do.
That's why you and I
get along so well.
I suppose it is.
But, in this case,
the truth is
we're going to get
you out of here, Major
and that's no platitude.
I must admit,
this is impressive work.
Incredible
is more like it.
He inventoried
the whole cargo bay
in under five hours.
You're sure
he didn't have any help?
According to the
internal sensors
no one else entered
that cargo bay
the entire time
he was there.
I guess he did learn something
working
in his uncle's storeroom.
I assume
that all of our equipment
is where it's supposed to be?
If you're asking
if he stole anything
the answer is no.
He even found some
things we missed
on our last
inventory.
Okay. So now we know
he's a hard worker.
The question remains
why does he want
to join Starfleet?
I have no idea.
I don't understand it.
I've run through
the entire
harmonic spectrum
and none of
the frequencies
have had any effect
on the crystal.
It's almost as if
the structure of
the crystal is mutating
to keep us from finding
the right frequency.
( weakly ):
Odo?
Yes, Major?
( gasps )
Oh, I wish there was
something else
I could do.
Just keep talking to me.
What do you
want me to say?
Anything.
Tell me a story.
A story?
I know.
Tell me how you
got your name.
My name?
Ah...
now that you mention it,
that is an amusing story.
Tell it to me.
Well...
as you know,
when Dr. Mora
first brought me
to his laboratory
it was under
Cardassian supervision.
All specimens
had to be
clearly labeled
in Cardassian
so the Overseers
would always know
what the scientists
were working on.
Since no one was
exactly sure what I was
Mora labeled me
"unknown sample"
which the Overseer
translated
into Cardassian
as odo'ital.
So your name
is "unknown sample"?
No... no.
Odo'ital literally means
the word "nothing."
Even after it became
clear that I was sentient
the Bajoran scientists
kept calling me that.
As a joke, they split
it into two words
like a Bajoran name:
"Odo Ital."
Which eventually
got shortened...
To Odo.
Ah.
( rumbling )
But now the thing is,
for the longest time
whenever anyone
would use my name
the first thing
I would think of
was what it meant:
"Nothing."
What better way
to describe me?
I had no family,
no friends
no place where
I belonged.
I thought it was
the most appropriate name
anyone could give me...
and then I met you...
and the others-- Sisko, Dax,
even Quark.
And now...
when I hear one of
you call me "Odo"
I no longer think of myself
as nothing.
I think of myself as me.
( weeping quietly )
I'm sorry, Major.
I guess that story
wasn't as amusing
as I hoped it would be.
No, I liked it very much.
The ultrasonic
generator
isn't going to work, is it?
No, I'm afraid it's not.
I don't suppose...
you have any other ideas?
( sighs )
I wish I had.
Neither do I.
It doesn't make sense.
The ultrasonic generator
should have worked.
Something's not right here.
Odo...
you've done
your best.
It's time for you to go.
Go?
This place is
going to collapse
any minute.
The Maquis is probably dead
from one of the cave-ins.
There's nothing more
you can do for me.
If you're asking me to leave...
As your superior officer
I'm telling you
to take the runabout
and get the hell
off this moon.
That's an order.
( gasping )
Odo, why are you
still standing there?
I told you
to get out of here.
I'm not leaving.
Constable, I gave you
a direct order.
You can order me all you want.
As of now,
I'm resigning my commission.
Odo, if you stay here,
you'll die.
You don't
know that
for certain!
And even if it were true,
I'm not going to abandon you.
I want you to get out of here.
Don't you understand?
I can't!
You have to.
Odo, please.
No, I won't leave you!
Why?!
Because!
Because...
I'm in love with you.
So...
now you know.
Odo...
I'm in love with you, too.
You wanted to see me, Commander?
Nog...
I've given your request
a lot of thought.
I appreciate that, Commander.
But I'm afraid I'm going
to have to turn you down.
Turn me down?
Why?
Did I do something wrong?
It's not anything
you did, Nog.
You're just not
Academy material.
Here...
this belongs to you.
Commander, can't we
talk about this?
There's nothing to talk about.
We both know you'd never make it
through the Academy.
You couldn't handle the workload
or the discipline.
You wouldn't last two weeks.
That's not true.
I'm a hard worker!
I proved that to you!
It doesn't matter.
And I'm not going to put
my reputation on the line
just to satisfy
some whim of yours.
It's not just a whim.
I'm serious
about joining Starfleet.
I don't have time
for this, Nog.
Now, whatever little scheme
you had, you can forget it.
I'm not giving you that letter.
It's not a joke
or a scheme.
I want to join
Starfleet.
I want it more
than anything
I've ever wanted
in my life.
You're a Ferengi.
Why would you want
to be in Starfleet?
Where's the profit in it?
I don't care
about profit!
Then what do
you care about?
Come on, Nog, tell me!
Why is it so damned important
that you get into Starfleet?
Why are you
doing this?
Because I don't want
to end up like my father!
Your... father.
That's right.
My father.
He's been chasing profit
his whole life
and what has it gotten him?
Nothing.
And you
know why?
Because he doesn't have
the lobes.
And neither do I.
And "a Ferengi
without profit..."
"...Is no Ferengi at all."
The 18th Rule of Acquisition.
My father
is a mechanical genius.
He could have been
Chief Engineer of a starship
if he'd had the opportunity.
But he went into business,
like a good Ferengi.
The only thing is, he's not
a good Ferengi.
Not when it comes
to acquiring profit.
So now, all he has to live for
is the slim chance
that someday, somehow
he might be able
to take over my uncle's bar.
Well, I'm not going to make
the same mistake.
I want to do something
with my life--
something
worthwhile.
Like joining Starfleet?
I may not have an
instinct for business
but I have
my Father's hands
and my Uncle's tenacity.
I know I've got
something to offer.
I just need the chance
to prove it.
All right.
I'll see
that you get that chance.
( laughs )
You're going to recommend me
to Starfleet Academy?!
I'll send the letter the first
thing tomorrow morning.
Commander, I don't
know how to thank you!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Don't thank me yet.
You still have a lot
of work ahead of you.
Don't worry.
You're never going
to regret this.
( strained ):
Odo?
Yes, Major?
You haven't said a word
to me in over an hour.
I've just been going over
a few things in my mind.
I'm sorry I
waited so long
to tell you
how I feel about you.
If I'd told
you earlier
maybe things would
have been different.
Ah.
What are you smiling about?
I think I've finally figured out
what's going on here.
This whole situation
hasn't seemed right
since the beginning.
There have been
too many coincidences
too many unanswered questions.
Are you still trying
to prove that this is
all some kind of conspiracy?
You said the Maquis was standing
here when he shot at you?
That's right.
How tall was he?
My height?
No...
maybe shorter.
Like this?
More or less.
What does it matter, anyway?
It matters
because, from this position
you're blocking
those phaser hits.
There's no way
someone standing here
could hit those rocks
without hitting you first.
Maybe he was standing
somewhere else.
Maybe...
or maybe you were lying to me.
Which makes two times
you've lied to me today.
What are you talking about?
You lied when you said
you were shot at by the Maquis
and you lied
when you said you loved me.
I do love you.
I wish you did, but you don't.
Remember, Major, I pride myself
on my ability to observe
human nature,
and I've watched you
for the past
three years.
In all that time,
I never saw any indication
that you had
those kind of feelings for me.
You like me...
you think of me
as a close friend...
but love?
I'm afraid not.
Maybe I told you I loved you
because I thought...
it would make you feel better.
Because I thought
that's what you wanted to hear.
You're lying again.
The Kira I know
has far too much regard
for our friendship
to lie to me...
even for the best
of reasons.
Odo, I can explain.
Good.
And you can start
by telling me
who you are and what
you've done with Kira.
Well done, Odo.
You really are
quite a skillful investigator.
( sighs )
And you're quite
a skillful changeling.
You still have
much to learn.
If you want to
share your wisdom
tell me where Major Kira is.
Close by.
You were the fugitive
we were chasing,
weren't you?
That's correct.
( sighs )
How did you get your hands
on a Maquis ship?
Now, Odo, you really
can't expect me
to give you
all the answers.
But why lead us here?
Why replace Major Kira?
( rumbling )
I needed to understand
why you chose
to live with the solids
rather than
your own people.
I suspected it had something
to do with Major Kira.
Now, I'm certain of it.
So your plan was
to let me think she died.
You thought that would take away
my link to the solids?
Then you would return to us.
I assure you nothing
will ever make me do that.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Tell me where she is.
And if I don't, then what?
You'll shoot me?
No changeling has
ever harmed another.
There's always
a first time.
Major Kira is
down that tunnel
200 meters
south of here.
Save her, if it suits you
but it won't make
any difference.
She is never going to love you.
How could she?
You are a changeling.
Major, wake up!
Odo, what happened?
What am I doing here?
It's a long story.
Right now, we have to get
you back to the Mekong.
There's one thing
I still don't understand.
If that Founder
was trying to test
your allegiance
to the solids
why did she
impersonate me?
I suppose it's because
you happened to be
with me in the runabout.
It could have just
as easily been
Commander Sisko,
Doctor Bashir...
What finally made you
realize the truth?
Well, she eventually
made a mistake.
She said something
I know you would never say.
What was that?
Just a slip
of the tongue...
nothing important.
I tell you,
I won't stand for it.
No nephew of mine
is going to disgrace
our family name
by joining
Starfleet.
But, Uncle Quark...
My mind is made up.
QUARK: I forbid it.
No, you don't.
Rom, stay out of this.
I will not.
When it comes to the bar,
you may be in charge
but, when it comes to my son,
I make the decisions.
Fine.
You tell him he can't go.
Nog...
good luck.
I would be proud
to have a son in Starfleet.
You're both insane.
Like father, like son.