SISKO:
Station Log, Stardate 48543.2.
A team of Cardassian scientists
is coming to the station
to assist us
in deploying a subspace relay
in the Gamma Quadrant.
If successful,
it will allow communication
through the wormhole
for the first time.
I've assigned
these quarters
to the senior Cardassian
scientist, her name is Ulani.
Her colleague, Gilora,
has the adjacent room.
It's warm in here.
I take it you reset
the environmental
controls.
I also had Chief
O'Brien reprogram
the replicators to provide
Cardassian food.
Security measures?
I've assigned
two of my people
to follow the Cardassians
at all times.
Fine, have them
keep their distance.
I want the Cardassians
to feel like guests,
not prisoners.
Commander, there are
still elements opposed
to the peace treaty
between Cardassia and Bajor
on both sides.
We have to be prepared
for trouble.
I realize that, but while
the Cardassians are here
I want the Bajorans
to get used to seeing them
walking on the Promenade...
buying from their shops,
eating from their
restaurants...
getting to know them
as something other
than brutal overseers.
( door opens )
I just received the final update
from the Cardassians
on the transceiver they designed
for the communications relay.
How does it look?
I'm still not convinced
it's going to work.
The Cardassians seem
sure that it will.
I hope
they're right.
Whose quarters
are these--
Gilora's or Ulani's?
Ulani's.
And how do you know
their names?
I was just informed
an hour ago.
Odo, please...
I have a bottle of kanar
for each of them...
along with a personal
invitation to Quark's.
Where did you get real kanar?
I've had three cases
in my storeroom
since the occupation.
There hasn't been much call
for it the past few years...
but that's about to change.
There are only two Cardassians
coming to the station.
How much kanar do you think
they can drink?
There may only be two for now,
but there'll be more
thanks to the peace treaty.
And as the 34th Rule
of Acquisition states
"Peace is good for business."
That's the 35th Rule.
Oh, you're right.
What's the 34th?
"War is good for business."
It's easy to get them confused.
The way I see it,
it won't be long
before there's
a permanent
Cardassian presence
on the station...
scientists,
diplomats...
spies.
And they'll all
be welcome at Quark's.
As long as they can pay.
Rumor has it that the
shop next door to mine
is going out of business.
I'm thinking of renting it
and setting up
a few Cardassian
gaming concessions.
There'll be no live vole fights
on the Promenade, Quark.
I would never
be party
to anything so cruel
and inhumane.
But, of course,
if some Cardassians
happen to bring
their voles along
and they happened
to get into a fight
I could hardly be
held responsible for...
Oh, yes, you could.
And you will be.
Fine.
Forget the vole fights.
But I'll
tell you this.
Good kanar
is hard to find.
And I have
three cases of it.
But that's just
the beginning.
Soon, Quark's will become
known as the best place
for Cardassian food and drink
in this sector.
I'll probably set up
daily shipments from Cardassia.
I may even
need to buy my own
transport ship.
Quark, this kanar
has gone bad.
What?!
I suggest you take
your bottles
and leave, Quark
before I have
you arrested
for attempting
to poison our guests.
Excuse me, Commander.
There's a Vedek Yarka
here to see you.
He says
it's urgent.
Thank you for seeing me,
Emissary.
What can I do for you?
I am here with a warning
from the Prophets.
They don't want you
to let the Cardassians
come aboard this station.
If you do, you will bring
destruction on us all.
( sighs )
Are you making some
sort of threat, Vedek?
Not at all.
I'm simply telling you
what was foretold
in the ancient texts.
Ancient texts...
you mean a prophecy?
Trakor's Third.
When he first encountered
the Orb of Change.
I'm afraid I
don't know it.
Perhaps you should
make more time
to study the
texts, child.
Are you saying
that the arrival
of the Cardassian scientists
was foretold
in a Bajoran prophecy?
Exactly.
Trakor's words are clear.
"When the river wakes, stirred
once more to Janir's side
three vipers will return
to their nest in the sky."
The river has
awoken, Emissary.
The Qui'al Dam was just
put back into operation
to divert water
to the city.
Just as Trakor prophesied
over 3,000 years ago.
And even now, the vipers
are making their way here.
And I take it
you think the vipers
are a reference
to the Cardassian scientists?
Yes, and this station
is their nest in the sky.
And how exactly
is their presence here
going to bring destruction
on us all?
Trakor said
"When the vipers try to peer
through the temple gates
"a sword of stars
will appear in the heavens.
The temple will burn, and
the gates will be cast open."
You must not let
the Cardassians come here.
You must not let them
violate the Celestial Temple
or they will destroy it
and Bajor will be cut off
from the Prophets forever.
Slow down.
Now, let me get this straight.
You're saying that the vipers--
the Cardassians--
are going to destroy
the wormhole?
Don't you see?
This communications relay
you hope to create
is part of the prophecy.
It will allow the vipers to peer
through the temple gates--
the wormhole, as you call it.
And if they do, the temple
will be destroyed.
Even if we accept that the
Cardassians are the vipers
there are only two of
them coming, not three.
Isn't it possible
that there are
other mistakes
in your interpretation
of the prophecy as well?
There will be three vipers,
you will see.
SISKO:
Do you understand what
this communications relay
could mean for Bajor?
If it works,
we'll be able to stay in contact
with ships
in the Gamma Quadrant.
It'll facilitate exploration
help us monitor
Dominion activity
give us warning
in case of an attack.
None of that matters.
You must listen to me.
I know it is difficult
for you to accept
because you are not Bajoran.
I have studied the prophecies
all my life.
We are on the verge
of a great disaster.
Is the Bajoran Assembly
aware of this prophecy?
Yes...
as is the Kai herself.
Yet, they still want us
to proceed
with the establishment
of a communications relay.
They have chosen
to ignore the signs.
And that is why I came
to you, Emissary
because I have faith in you.
I know that you will do
what must be done.
Vedek...
I have the utmost respect
for your beliefs
but I have no intention
of calling this project off.
I hope that you will
reconsider, Emissary.
My followers and I
will remain on the station
and pray that you
change your mind.
You are free to do that,
of course.
Major, have Odo find out
everything he can
about Vedek Yarka
and his followers.
I don't want them
making any trouble
while the Cardassians
are here.
( sighs )
I'm Commander Benjamin Sisko
and, on behalf of the
United Federation of Planets
and Starfleet Command
I'd like to welcome you
to Deep Space 9.
Thank you, Commander.
I'm Dr. Ulani Belor.
Gilora Rejal.
The Cardassian
government
wishes to express
its gratitude
to the Federation
for agreeing
to work together
on this project.
It is our hope that it is the
first of many such projects
between
our peoples.
That's a hope I can
assure you we share.
This is my First
Officer, Major Kira.
And on behalf of the Bajoran
provisional government
I'd like to welcome you.
It is our belief
that this project
will mark the beginning
of a new era of peace
for Bajor
and Cardassia.
Thank you, Major.
Well...
now that we've gotten the
formalities out of the way
how was your trip?
Exhausting.
We spent most of it
rehearsing
what we were going to say
when we got here.
We're scientists,
not diplomats.
You did very well.
Please feel free to let
the Central Command know that.
In the past few days
I've been contacted by Guls
I haven't even heard of
all of them wanting to emphasize
how important this mission is.
I know what you mean.
I've gotten three calls
from Starfleet Command
just this morning.
( laughs )
Major Kira
I want to thank you personally
for allowing us to come here.
Me?
You're the ranking
Bajoran officer
on this station.
I'm sure we wouldn't be here
if you had been opposed
to working with us.
I'll work with anyone
who's interested in peace.
I'm glad we already
have so much in common.
Well, why don't I show you
to your quarters?
The signaling platform
we've designed
is intended to be positioned
in the Gamma Quadrant,
at this point--
two kilometers from the
far mouth of the wormhole.
Our transceiver is being
configured to fit inside it
and use its
existing power grid.
GILORA:
A similar transceiver
will be put in place
here on Terok Nor--
on Deep Space 9.
Ulani, I've looked over
your design specifications.
I'm not clear on what
sort of carrier wave
you're planning on using
to cut through
the interference
on the inside
of the wormhole.
We're planning to test various
types of soliton pulses.
One of them
should maintain
the required
signal integrity.
We tried something similar about
a year ago without much success.
Yes, the Bajoran
government
made your data
available to us.
I believe the problem
had to do with
the phase variance
in your transceiver coils.
Well, I configured
those coils myself.
The variance was less
than .01 percent.
Which, as you saw,
was unacceptably high.
Our new design has less
than half that variance.
You don't mind
if I look at the specs?
If you think
it's necessary.
Commander...
we'll need to make
a few adjustments
to the station's
signaling array
so that it
can accommodate
the type of
transmissions
we're planning
to use.
Chief O'Brien's people
can assist you with that.
And when you're ready
we'll take the Defiant
to the Gamma Quadrant
deploy the communications relay
and start running tests.
Excellent.
Well, it's been
a long day.
We'd like to get some rest
so we can start fresh tomorrow.
I'll have someone
show you to
your quarters.
Thank you, but that
won't be necessary.
Thank you.
Now, those are about
the two friendliest vipers
I have ever met.
I'll explain later.
( door opens )
Commander, I almost
forgot to tell you.
Another colleague
of ours, Dejar
will be arriving later today.
I'll arrange quarters.
Thank you.
So...
we need to discuss
what we're going
to do about...
What is it, Major?
There are going to be
three of them.
Yes?
Three vipers...
just like
in the prophecy.
ODO:
It turns out that Vedek Yarka
is no longer a Vedek at all.
He was stripped of his
title two months ago.
Why?
Officially, for teachings
not in keeping with
the Bajoran faith.
But according to my sources,
he was defrocked because he led
a series of protests
against the Vedek Assembly
when they endorsed the peace
treaty with Cardassia.
So Yarka may be
using this prophecy
as a way to scuttle
the peace treaty.
That would seem
to be his agenda.
And it's probably coloring
his view of the prophecy
just as your agenda
colors how you see it.
I don't have an agenda, Odo.
I want this project to succeed
because I want
the peace treaty to succeed.
If I thought for a moment
that there was any possibility
that this communications relay
could cause damage
to the wormhole
I'd put a stop to it right now.
That's not the agenda
I was referring to, Commander.
Oh?
I was referring
to your desire
to distance yourself
from the title of Emissary.
It's just an observation,
of course
but it's always seemed to me
that you've never been
comfortable with it.
( sighs )
I can't deny that.
Are you suggesting
that I'm dismissing
this prophecy too easily
because I don't want
to be the Emissary?
I'm not suggesting
anything
but it's been my experience
that all humanoids have
an agenda of some sort
and that their agendas
can influence them
without their even realizing it.
Morn came by the Infirmary
this afternoon.
He had an acute case
of food poisoning.
Morn? I didn't think anything
could make him sick.
Well, he said he had
a bad glass of
kanar at Quark's.
He should ask
for a refund.
Apparently, it was
on the house.
Major, may I have
a word with you?
I'll see
you later.
What can I do
for you, Vedek?
Have you been able to
convince the Emissary
to reconsider
his decision?
I haven't tried
and I'm not planning to.
But you must.
If not, the Celestial
Temple will be destroyed.
I'm not convinced
that's going to happen.
Don't you believe
in the prophecies?
Yes.
And don't you believe
that Commander Sisko
is the Emissary?
Vedek, you have to understand
my position here.
Commander Sisko is
my superior officer.
I have to deal with him
on that basis first.
So you do believe
he is the Emissary.
You just don't want
him to know that.
I understand.
You want him to know
that he can count
on you as an officer
under his command.
You want to keep your work
and your faith separate.
Yes, and for three
years now, I have.
I'm afraid
that's no longer possible.
The Prophets have chosen you
to help the Emissary
make this decision.
A decision that has profound
implications for all of Bajor.
You must convince him
to make the Cardassians leave
before the sword of stars
appears.
Vedek, if you're asking me to...
It is not I who is asking,
it is the Prophets.
If you turn your back
on them now
you're abandoning your faith.
And without your faith, Nerys
what do you have left?
I prefer
the serialist poets
from the First Republic,
like Iloja of Prim.
He's easily my favorite
Cardassian writer.
It is so rare to meet
a non-Cardassian
who appreciates
our literature.
I took an interest
because I had the
chance to meet Iloja.
You knew him?
One of my
previous hosts
Tobin, met him while he
was in exile on Vulcan.
As I recall, he had
quite a temper.
Really?
QUARK:
I believe this is the
party you're looking for.
ULANI:
Dejar.
May I introduce
Jadzia Dax
and Miles
O'Brien.
Our colleague,
Dejar.
We weren't expecting
you so soon.
I was able to arrange
special transportation.
I'm sure you were.
I took the liberty
of preparing
a few of our special
Cardassian delicacies.
Tojal in
yamok sauce.
Regova eggs.
All fresh,
not replicated.
Well, enjoy.
Is something wrong?
It's just...
I don't really care
for Cardassian cuisine.
GILORA:
We try to avoid it
whenever possible.
( chuckling )
Fortunately, those of us
in the Science Ministry
are provided with a wide variety
of off-world food.
Yes, we're
actually quite spoiled.
Some of us even think
of ourselves
as better
than the average Cardassian.
The main switching
relays are in here.
I think we should hook
your transceiver
to the ODN interface
through the...
What happened to
these couplings?
What? Oh, I-I made
some modifications.
Well, these relays
don't have nearly
as much carrying
capacity as before.
They won't be able to handle
the signal load
from the transceiver.
Well, in order
to bring the system
up to Starfleet code, I had
to take out the couplings
to make room
for a secondary backup.
Starfleet code requires
a second backup?
In case the first one fails.
What are the chances that
both a primary system
and its backup would
fail at the same time?
Well, it's very unlikely,
but, in a crunch
I wouldn't like to be caught
without a second backup.
Well!
( pounds fist )
What's done is done.
I'll try to figure out
what we should do next.
Well, I think our best
bet would be to go...
Please, please just
give me a moment to think.
Fine.
I'll just sit
here quietly.
Huh. In that case,
could you get me
a cup of red leaf tea?
Why not?
We've loaded
the communications relay
into the Defiant's cargo bay.
Good.
How are Chief O'Brien
and Gilora coming along?
They've run into
some kind of problem
but the Chief says
the transceiver
should be on line
in about four hours.
We won't be ready much
before that anyway.
DAX:
We've received clearance
from Ops, Commander.
Release docking clamps
and set a course
for the wormhole.
Full scan.
No sign of Dominion activity.
No other ships in the area.
SISKO:
All right, take
us into position.
Stand by to deploy the relay...
Wait a minute.
What is it?
I'm reading a large mass
of ice and ionized gas
entering
sensor range
bearing 215 mark 3.
It looks like a rogue comet.
Let's have a look.
Put it on screen.
It's beautiful.
DAX:
Its core contains
unusually high concentrations
of silithium.
That's why its tail
is so bright.
The sword of stars.
That's a very
colorful way
to describe
a comet, Major.
It's just a figure of speech.
Well, your sword of stars
is going to pass
very near the wormhole
but not close enough
to interfere with our plans.
We're in position, Benjamin.
Begin a final systems check
on the relay station.
I want to deploy it
within the hour.
Major, can I have
a word with you?
The sword of stars?
It certainly looked
like that to me.
That's open to debate
but what is not debatable
is that this prophecy
has no place
on the Bridge of the Defiant
especially in front
of the Cardassians.
At the moment, they are
not even aware of it
and I want
to keep it that way.
You're right.
It won't happen again.
Well...
I take it, Major
that you believe
the prophecy is coming true.
Yes, I do.
So you think I should
call this mission off?
Look at what's
happened already.
The river has returned to Janir,
the three vipers
now the sword of stars--
each of them predicted
by Trakor's prophecy.
And then
there's you...
the Emissary.
You're here.
You have a decision to make,
just like in the prophecy.
Do you really believe
that I'm the Emissary?
I guess I always have.
I... never wanted
to admit it to myself.
It's hard to work for someone
who's a religious icon.
( sighs )
I hope I don't offend
your beliefs
but I don't see myself as an
icon, religious or otherwise.
I'm a Starfleet officer, and
I have a mission to accomplish.
If I call it off, it has to be
for some concrete reason
something solid,
something Starfleet.
All right,
how about this?
The Prophets...
the aliens who live
in the wormhole
as you call them
exist outside
of linear time.
They know the past,
present and future.
Agreed.
It seems perfectly
reasonable
that they could've
communicated
their knowledge
of the future
to a Bajoran
named Trakor.
He wrote down
that knowledge
in the form
of a prophecy
and now, 3,000
years later
we are seeing
those events unfold.
To me, that reasoning
sounds concrete, solid.
I'd even call it
"Starfleet."
( chuckles )
But that all hinges
on how you interpret
an ancient text
that's been translated
and retranslated
over the centuries.
Words that were couched
in metaphor to begin with.
I'm sorry, Major
but where you see
a sword of stars
I see a comet.
Where you see vipers,
I see three scientists.
And where you see the Emissary
I see a Starfleet officer.
Dax to Sisko.
Go ahead.
We're ready to deploy the relay.
On my way.
( sighs )
All right.
Now we just have
to shunt the ODN line
through the secondary
field coils.
We can't do that.
Why not?
Because those coils
aren't configured
to handle ODN output.
Why not?
Did you modify them, too?
Actually,
I replaced them.
They were always
shorting out on us.
Frankly, I don't
see how this station
kept running during
the occupation.
Why didn't you tell me
you'd replaced
the secondary field coils?
If you had told me
what you were planning
to do, I would have.
I don't have time
to explain everything.
What? You think I won't
be able to understand?
It has been
my experience that it...
What?
That humans aren't
good engineers?
No, not humans-- males.
I beg your pardon?
Men just don't seem to have
a head for this sort of thing.
That's why women
dominate the sciences.
Maybe on Cardassia,
but on this station
this man is
Chief of Operations
and I know more
about these systems
than anyone,
including you.
I think I know
what the problem is
so if you want to get
that transceiver on line
hand me the laser-torch
and give me some room.
( sighs )
Are we ready on this end?
Almost. I'm just
about to activate
the relay's
transmission array.
Dejar?
Standing by.
I am receiving
the relay's test signal.
Target the signaling array
toward the wormhole
and initiate
a carrier wave
in the delta
band frequency.
Initiating carrier wave.
If they receive it
on the station
they'll send
an acknowledging signal
in the same frequency.
I'm not receiving anything.
Then we have to assume
it didn't work.
Let's try
the theta band frequency.
Initiating carrier wave.
Something's wrong.
I'm picking up a neutrino surge
from the wormhole.
Report!
Somehow the carrier wave
caused the wormhole to open.
The wormhole's gravity well has
increased by a factor of three.
Terminate the carrier wave
and maintain our position.
Gravimetric fields
have returned
to normal.
What happened?
I'm not sure.
The carrier wave shouldn't have
affected the wormhole at all.
Was there any damage
to the relay?
None. I'm still receiving
the test signal.
Benjamin,
the gravitational surge
altered the course of the comet.
It's now heading directly
toward the wormhole.
If the comet enters the wormhole
the silithium in its core
will cause
a cascade reaction.
And collapse the wormhole
permanently.
Commander's Log, supplemental.
With less than five hours
before the comet
reaches the wormhole
I've brought the Defiant
back to the station
and convened a meeting
of the entire science team.
DAX:
Apparently,
the carrier wave we sent
created some sort of
subspace inversion
inside the wormhole.
That's what caused
the gravity well to form.
ULANI:
The possibility
of subspace inversion
was predicted in one
of our computer
models.
Well, that wasn't
included
in the data
you sent us.
The probability
of such an occurrence
was less than two percent--
well within safety limits.
We saw no reason to include it
in the data we sent you.
It would seem that our
scientific methodologies
differ slightly.
It is our practice to examine
all possibilities
no matter how unlikely, before
we proceed with field tests.
We would, of course
prefer to operate
that way, as well.
However, since
the Science Ministry
falls under the jurisdiction
of the military
we have to follow
certain rules.
One of them is not
to make any project
look unnecessarily
dangerous.
We'll keep that in mind
when we resume work
on the communications relay.
DEJAR:
That is an extremely
unlikely possibility, Commander.
The Science Ministry
will undoubtedly wish
to assemble a new team
before proceeding
further.
SISKO:
That is,
of course
an internal Cardassian matter.
Chief...
Dax feels
we can't risk
using tractor beams
to deflect the comet.
It would probably
break into smaller pieces
and we'd have
a bigger mess on our hands.
The same thing
would happen
if you tried
to destroy it
with a phaser beam.
Not necessarily.
I could modify the
Defiant's phaser array
to generate a beam
wide enough
to encompass
the entire comet.
Vaporizing it evenly,
so it won't break up.
How long would
the modifications take?
Three hours.
Get on it.
We'll be cutting this one
pretty close.
I've accessed
the Defiant's
primary phaser relay.
I'm going to try
shunting it
through the warp drive.
Won't that overload
the relay?
Not if we bypass
the plasma emitter.
I hadn't thought
of that.
( stammering )
The emitter coupling
is over there.
What are you
doing now?
I'm decoupling
the servos
so they don't
lock up.
You have very steady hands.
Well they get the job done,
I guess.
And right now,
the most important job
is bypassing the
plasma emitter.
I assure you,
I'm quite fertile.
I could provide you
with many healthy children
if that's your concern,
but, quite frankly
I think you're getting
a little ahead of yourself.
Children?
What are you talking about?
I already have a child
and a wife.
You're married?
Yes, happily!
Then why have you been
leading me to believe
that you wanted me?
I haven't.
All we've done
since we've met is argue.
I took your overt irritability
toward me as a signal
that you wished to pursue
some physical relationship.
Of course.
Well, that's how Cardassians,
uh, do things?
Oh, my.
I'm afraid
this is a case
of cross-cultural
misunderstanding.
I think so.
Oh.
I'm not remotely
interested in you.
Well, that's not
what I meant.
Look, you are very attractive
and I'm flattered,
of course. but...
Please, Mr. O'Brien
there's no need
to continue.
You've made your
feelings clear.
Gilora, we-we have
to finish this.
I'm sure you can complete
the job on your own.
Chief O'Brien
said the modification
to the Defiant's phasers
would be ready
within half an hour.
Half an hour ahead
of schedule, hmm?
The Chief's
a born engineer.
He always gives himself
a comfortable margin
with his repair estimates.
Let me guess.
You're reading up
on Bajoran prophecies
concerning the Emissary.
There are hundreds of them.
Most of them are vague,
some are contradictory.
But just enough truth in
a few of them to make me wonder.
You mean some of them
have come true?
If you interpret them
in a certain way, yes.
So now you're wondering
if Trakor's prophecy
is going to come true,
as well.
I have to admit,
it's getting harder to ignore.
But, Benjamin,
there's every reason
to believe we'll be able
to destroy the comet.
I know.
But I'm becoming
more and more concerned
that if I don't send
the Cardassians home
something else will go wrong.
And the "gates of heaven
will burn and be cast open."
Let me ask you something.
If you never heard
Trakor's prophecy
what would you do?
I'd continue working
on the communications relay.
Then it seems to me
you have a choice.
You can either
make your own decisions
or you can let these prophecies
make them for you.
As soon as the Defiant is ready
have the Cardassians
meet us on board.
Yes, sir.
The comet is directly ahead.
Distance, 200 kilometers.
Bring us to within
ten kilometers.
Chief, are your phaser
modifications on line?
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir.
Phasers are locked on target.
Holding position
at ten kilometers.
SISKO:
Shields up.
Go to Red Alert.
Fire!
Chief, what the hell happened?
I don't know, sir.
The entire weapons
relay just blew.
All defensive
systems are down.
Benjamin, the sensors show
that the modified phasers
never came on line.
We fired a standard burst
and it shattered the comet
instead of vaporizing it.
There's no way they should have
misfired like that.
I modified the systems myself.
KIRA:
Commander, the
three fragments
are still on course
for the wormhole.
How soon before
they reach the entrance?
26 minutes.
And without weapons,
we have no way of stopping them.
The main emitter coupling
has been depolarized.
I must have accidentally
inverted the power flow
when I tried to modify
the phaser array.
I can't believe it.
A first-year
engineering student
wouldn't make a
mistake like that.
This wasn't your
fault, Mr. O'Brien.
And it wasn't
an accident.
Gilora...
Dejar is a member
of the Obsidian Order.
She was assigned
to our team
for security reasons.
I believe
she sabotaged
this coupling.
SISKO:
The Order has always
been opposed
to the peace treaty
with Bajor.
They sent you here
to sabotage the relay
because if the
first joint venture
between Cardassia and
Bajor was a failure
it would probably
be the last.
This is all speculation,
Commander.
You have no proof.
If it was sabotage, a DNA
scan on the coupling
should reveal
who's responsible.
Take her to quarters
and detain her there.
SISKO:
Now that the comet's
been fractured
into smaller pieces
can we use the tractor
beams to deflect them?
They'd just
disintegrate further
releasing more silithium.
If we can't
stop the fragments
is there any way that we
can prevent the silithium
from interacting
with the wormhole?
Maybe if we could
contain it somehow.
ULANI:
If you could generate
a subspace field
around the fragments
that might contain
the silithium.
The warp drive...
it could create a subspace
bubble around the ship.
But we'd have
to maneuver the Defiant
between the fragments.
They're too close together.
There's not enough room.
A shuttlepod could
maneuver between them.
And its warp drive
should be able to create
a large enough
subspace field.
Maybe, but it could
overload the engines.
That's the chance
I'll have to take.
Major, you have the Bridge.
I want you to take the Defiant
back into the Alpha Quadrant
as soon as I've cleared
the shuttlebay.
Commander.
I want to go with you.
Not just because I'm
your First Officer
but because I believe I'm
here to help the Emissary.
Dax, the Bridge
is yours.
We've cleared
the shuttlebay.
Signal the Defiant
that they can leave.
They're heading
for the wormhole.
I'm going to take us in
behind the
comet fragments.
It'll be easier to
maneuver into position.
Hold position here.
They could be in
for a rough ride.
Stand by transporters
in case we need
to beam them off the shuttlepod
when they clear the wormhole.
We're in position.
Activate the
subspace field.
Field engaged.
We'll reach the entrance
to the wormhole in...
five seconds.
The subspace field
is losing integrity.
Some of the silithium
is starting to leak through.
Divert power
from the engines
to the subspace field coils.
We'll let our
own inertia
carry us the
rest of the way.
That helped.
We're still losing silithium.
I'm picking up a neutrino surge.
Something's coming through.
( sighs )
Dax to Sisko.
Sisko here.
Are you all right, Benjamin?
There was some silithium leakage
inside the wormhole,
but we're fine.
I don't believe it.
What is it, Chief?
I'm picking up the test signal
from the communications relay.
SISKO:
How is that possible?
DAX:
I'm not sure.
We're reading
a subspace filament
leading back through
the wormhole.
It's acting like some kind
of carrier wave.
The comet fragments...
they must have left a silithium
trail in the wormhole.
It's almost like
the wormhole
was wedged open
just a crack...
just enough to let
subspace signals through.
The prophecy came true...
all of it.
We just misinterpreted
Trakor's words.
The three vipers.
He wasn't talking
about the Cardassians.
He meant the three
comet fragments.
The communications relay.
In a sense, we've been trying
to peer
through the temple gates.
The silithium
ignited the wormhole
burning the temple gates.
So that they never close again.
And it's
all because
the Emissary...
used the sword of stars.
And Trakor saw it all...
3,000 years ago.
I just want to say
that I appreciate
what you did
on the Defiant.
I hope it doesn't cause
you too much trouble
when you get
back to Cardassia.
My superiors in the Science
Ministry will protect me.
Frankly, I think Dejar's
in much more trouble than I.
The Order doesn't
reward failure.
Still, it was
a brave thing to do.
I didn't want you
to take the blame
for something that
wasn't your fault.
I know how proud you are
of your work.
Too proud, sometimes.
It's gotten me into trouble,
now and again.
What's your wife's name?
Keiko.
A lucky woman.
Emissary, I'm sorry
I doubted you.
I realize now I let my
distrust of the Cardassians
blind me to the
Prophets' words.
It seems that the
Prophets want peace
between your two
peoples, after all.
Perhaps so.
There are signs that
Trakor's Fourth Prophecy
will soon come
to pass, as well.
Don't tell me that it has
something to do with me.
You, Commander?
Well, it is a prophecy
about the Emissary.
Tell me about it.
Trakor's Fourth Prophecy
says that the Emissary
will face a fiery trial
and he'll be forced to choose...