It's all right, Chief.
You're going to be just fine.
What happened?
You were rerouting
a phase inducer
when one of the plasma
conduits blew out.
Oh.
Easy there, Chief.
You've got a mild case
of radiation poisoning.
I'll give you some
hyronalin which should
counteract the effects,
but I do think
he should be restricted
to light duty
for the next few days.
Agreed.
Commander,
the transport's arrived
and they're requesting
permission to dock.
Route them to Docking Bay 12.
Inform the Romulan Delegation
we'll meet
them there.
( groans )
And, Chief, "light duty"
means light.
I don't want
to see you crawling around
the Jefferies tube tonight
looking for power surges.
You won't get any arguments
today, Commander.
Ready, Major?
Promenade.
KLINGON: Du'cha KovaH!
EstaH! EstaH!
Constable,
I wasn't aware
there were any Klingons
on the station.
They just arrived
a few hours ago.
It seems the main computer
on their freighter was damaged
and they need
a complete overhaul
before they can continue
back to the Klingon Empire.
How long is this overhaul
going to take?
( belches )
Two days, at least.
The Romulan delegation
has just arrived
and they're going to be here
at least two days
while they study
our intelligence reports
on the Dominion.
I want you to keep a close eye
on the Klingons.
We don't need
any trouble right now.
Understood.
Let's go.
Come on.
Welcome to Deep Space 9.
I'm Commander Sisko,
and this is
my first Officer,
Major Kira.
I am Ruwon.
This is Karina.
We are ready for your report
on the Dominion.
We have arranged
quarters for you.
I know it's been
a long trip, so
perhaps you'd like...
We are not interested
in your accommodations,
Commander.
We are here for
your intelligence briefing--
nothing else.
Very well.
If you'll
come this way.
This will be
the foul line.
We need to put a marker
here on the floor.
I still don't see how
this is going to help
my business, Chief.
No, that's not right.
The number 20 needs
to be at the top.
Trust me, Quark.
Darts and bars go together
like bacon and eggs.
At least people order
bacon and eggs.
In all the years
I've been here,
no one has ever come
and asked to see
the dart board.
Trust me, they will.
I just don't see the
appeal of this game.
No lasers, no holograms.
Just steel tips
and feathers.
It's a game of skill, Quark.
And it's not easy.
Go ahead.
Try and get one
in the bull's-eye.
( sighs )
No!
Now what if one of those darts
had gotten into his eye?
Do you realize
I'd be liable for that?
Do you know how much
money an eye costs?
You're not supposed to
throw them like that.
You throw them gently.
One at a time.
Like this.
QUARK: Chief O'Brien.
O'BRIEN: What is it, Quark?
The Klingons
just destroyed two
of my holosuites.
I need a maintenance
crew immediately.
Quark, this happens
every time the Klingons
come aboard the station.
O'BRIEN:
Why don't you just keep
them out of the holosuites?
Did you ever say no
to a Klingon?
Besides, they pay me double.
Chief?
Chief!
Well, the pain
you experienced
appears to be
a muscle spasm
caused by a
sudden decrease
in your serum
calcium levels.
It's a common
side effect
of radiation
poisoning.
I'm giving you some
asinolyathin for the pain.
What about
the vision I had?
Well, mild
hallucinations
are also a fairly
common side effect
of radiation
poisoning.
It was anything but mild.
I really felt I was
standing on the Promenade
watching myself
talking to Quark.
What was the
conversation about?
He was complaining
about some Klingons.
He said they'd damaged
two of his holosuites.
Well, you do have
one problem.
If all you can hallucinate
about is Quark's
maintenance problems,
you have a sadly
deficient fantasy life.
( chuckles )
Well, thank you for
your professional opinion.
Oh, any time.
My doors are always
open to you, Chief.
RUWON:
The Dominion represents
the greatest threat
to the Alpha Quadrant
in the last century.
We need more information
on its military
capabilities.
How many ships
do they have?
Where are they
deployed?
What are their plans
for the future?
Are they planning
an attack?
We don't know
any of that yet.
You have one of Founders
of the Dominion
on this very station.
He should be able to tell us
everything we need to know
about their intentions.
Odo is not one
of the Founders.
Your own reports indicate
that a group of changelings
are the real source of power
behind the Dominion.
KIRA: Yes.
And Odo is a changeling.
But he's not one
of the Founders.
I fail to see
the distinction.
Odo made a conscious choice
to stay here with us.
He has no loyalties
to the Dominion
and he has no information
about their plans.
We find that
hard to believe.
It's the truth, whether you
choose to believe it or not.
Commander, we allowed you
to place one of our cloaking
devices on the Defiant
in exchange for information
regarding the Dominion.
Now you have
the cloaking device,
and we have very little.
KARINA:
We shouldn't have to remind you
of the importance
both our governments place
on continuing to carry out
this agreement.
It's the first treaty between
Romulus and the Federation
in many years.
I'm aware of that,
and I'm willing to cooperate
with you in any way I can.
Very well, then.
We want to see
every piece of information
Starfleet has on the Dominion,
no matter how insignificant.
That includes
any classified reports
you may have made
to Starfleet Command.
I'll have to clear that
with Starfleet.
Then do it.
QUARK:
Chief O'Brien.
What is it, Quark?
The Klingons just destroyed
two of my holosuites.
I need a maintenance
crew immediately.
Quark, we go through this
every time Klingons
come aboard the station.
Why don't you ju...?
I think my holosuites
can wait.
It looks like you have
bigger problems.
I went over
the internal sensor logs
and I did find evidence
of a minor temporal
disturbance in Quark's
and another one later,
on the Promenade.
Both disturbances happened
at about the same time
as the Chief's experiences.
So, it would seem
that you did travel
into the future
and then returned
to the same moment
that you left.
Have you any idea what might
have caused this time shift?
Not yet.
I want to go over
the medical scans
Julian took of you earlier.
That dose of ionizing
radiation you received
might have something
to do with it.
How?
I'm not sure,
but it's a good
place to start.
I have heard
a couple of theories
that ambient
low-level radiation
could have
a temporal...
( people shouting )
( glass shattering )
Look out!
DAX: ...effect on
radioactive isotopes.
( O'Brien thuds to ground )
Chief!
Mr. O'Brien.
I ran a microcellular scan
and detected minute damage
to his cerebrospinal nerve cells
which might have been caused
by the time-shifting.
Can you repair it?
Yes.
But the effect is cumulative.
If you keep time-shifting,
there may come a point
where the damage
becomes irreparable.
Eventually, it might
even kill you.
( sighs )
SISKO:
Don't worry, Chief--
Dax is using
every scanner on the station
to hunt for
any temporal abnormalities.
Well, if anyone
can find the cause
of the time shifts, it's Dax.
Chief, do you have any idea
of how far into the future
you traveled?
No, sir. There was
nothing to indicate
that it was today,
tomorrow, next week.
Well, this conference
with the Romulans
is not supposed to last
longer than three days.
In the meantime,
I'll have Odo
tighten security
around Quark's.
How are you feeling,
Chief?
Better.
Good.
Commander, may I speak
with you for a minute?
Of course.
The Romulans want
to debrief everyone
who was on the Defiant
when it was captured
by the Founders.
They're also still not happy
with the sensor information
collected by the Defiant,
so they want unrestricted
access to the Defiant
and they also want
complete access to
all our personal logs.
Personal logs are
out of the question,
but they can have limited
access to the Defiant.
I'll let them
debrief us as well.
( exasperated sigh )
I know they're
pushing us, Major,
but consider
their position.
There have never been
any Romulan ships in
the Gamma Quadrant
so they've never
encountered the Dominion.
So they're completely
dependent on us
for information.
Well, then maybe they should
send their own ships
through the wormhole
and find out for themselves.
The Romulans generally
prefer to sit back
and pull the strings from
a distance, if they can.
This is one puppet who doesn't
like her strings pulled.
I know, but
like Ruwon said,
they've lived up to their
part of the bargain.
We have to do
everything we can
to live up to ours.
All right, I'll draw up
a schedule of interviews
and I'll tell everyone
to cooperate.
And, Major, when you're
with the Romulans
try to be diplomatic.
I'm always
diplomatic.
That is the most ridiculous
thing I ever heard,
and I resent the implication.
You seem very agitated
for someone who's
proclaiming her innocence.
Indeed, your emotional state
would seem to indicate
that our theory is correct
and you did abandon
the Defiant prematurely
when it was attacked
by the Jem'Hadar.
( sighs )
When the Defiant
was attacked,
Odo and I were
trapped below decks.
There was a hand-to-hand
fight in the corridor.
I was wounded,
and I lost consciousness.
When I came to,
Odo had already put me
aboard the shuttle,
and we'd escaped.
I did not abandon
the ship prematurely.
Why didn't Odo try to help
the rest of
the Defiant's crew?
Well, I'm sure he wanted to,
but there was no way
to get to the Bridge, and...
Why were you in
Odo's quarters
when the ship was attacked?
We were talking.
About what?
It's personal.
Do you
often have
personal talks
with the changeling?
What business is that of yours?
We're trying to determine the
nature of your relationship.
You are the only
member of the
Defiant's crew
who was not taken
prisoner. Why?
Did the Founders
believe Odo would
react badly
if you were harmed?
Did they think you held
some kind of attraction to him?
Has Odo ever shown
any kind of physical
interest in you, Major?
That's it.
You can rip the cloaking device
out of the Defiant
right now!
I am not answering
any more questions.
And I suggest you avoid
asking Odo those questions
or you may just find yourself
on the other side of
that bulkhead, floating home.
There.
That's the game.
Had enough?
One more.
Chief, that's the tenth game
we've played in a row.
Nothing's happening here
and I don't think anything
is going to happen.
By telling us about
the fight, you have
changed the future.
Security's here,
and Quark says
he won't let the Klingons
back in the bar.
There is not going
to be a fight.
I know, I know, but...
I've seen it, and I
can't shake the feeling
that it's going to happen
despite our precautions.
Something about
the way things look,
the number of people.
There's something
a little too familiar
about everything.
All right, if it makes
you feel any better,
I'll beat you
at another ten games.
But I can't help
getting the feeling...
( loud laughter )
Ach'cho korvak bataH!
Karagh, abeH.
( laughter continues )
You said you weren't
going to let the Klingons
back in the bar!
I didn't.
They were in
the holosuites.
Besides, now they're
paying me triple.
( chuckling )
Who let these filthy
pahtk in here?
Maybe we should
show them the way out.
And then...
What's his name?
Ruwon?
Ruwon started
to insinuate that...
you were...
That I was what?
Interested in me.
He said that?
Have you ever heard
anything more...
Ridiculous!
Exactly.
Quark to Security.
I've got a fight on my hands.
They're tearing my place apart.
( people yelling )
Watch the Romulan!
All right, that's enough!
Get back! Come on!
ODO:
Move it.
Let's go.
Come on now.
Miles?
( gasps )
( groaning )
Chief. It's all right.
You collapsed outside Quark's
about an hour ago.
You're going to be fine.
No, I'm not.
In a few hours,
I'm going to be dead.
This is the panel
I saw myself open.
It looked like a phaser
or high-energy laser
came out
of the bulkhead.
Nothing
on the tricorder.
Just the standard conduits
and power juncture ports.
If there is something
dangerous in there,
it could be cloaked
or have some dampening field
around it.
If you gentlemen will
step down the corridor
I'll open the panel
and take a look.
Don't worry.
I'll be careful.
It's all right.
Nothing.
You're sure this
is the right panel?
Absolutely.
Believe me,
I've a pretty vivid memory
of the whole thing.
( sighs )
Well... since
it appears
that your first
two time jumps
each moved you
to about five hours
into the future,
we could also assume
that the incident you
saw in this corridor
moved you to about five
hours into the future.
ODO:
That means someone
will place a device
in this panel
in the next few hours.
All these quarters
are vacant
at the moment.
There are no vital power
conduits in this area.
No crucial
defense systems.
Why would someone
want to booby-trap
a wall panel here?
I suggest we place
a surveillance device
in this corridor.
If anyone attempts
to tamper with the panel,
we'll be able to detect it.
Dax to Sisko.
Sisko here.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
Benjamin,
can you come to Ops?
I think I've found a clue to
Chief O'Brien's time-shifting.
We're on our way.
Keep me informed.
DAX:
I've been scanning the area
around the station
out to a radius
of two kilometers.
I didn't find anything at first.
Then I started to scan some of
the lower subspace bandwidths.
I found traces of low-level
tetryon emissions.
I've never seen
an emission pattern
like that
outside
of a neutron star.
Or a quantum singularity.
And singularities are
known to send out waves
of temporal displacement.
But if there is
a singularity nearby,
why can't we find it?
It should also
be affecting
the gravimetric
field signatures.
I don't know.
Maybe it's buried so far down
in the subspace layers
that we can't detect it.
Assuming
for the moment
that a singularity
is responsible,
how do we combat
its effects on the Chief?
Temporal displacement
caused by a quantum singularity
most commonly affects
delta-series radioisotopes,
which is exactly
what the Chief absorbed
during the conduit breach.
So you're saying
that it could be pulling
O'Brien's body like a magnet?
Exactly. I think I may
know a way to neutralize
the remaining radioisotopes
in your body.
DAX: Without the radiation,
the temporal displacement
might stop.
It's going to take time.
You may experience
one or two
more time shifts
before I can
complete the process.
When can we start?
Right away.
Keep trying to pinpoint
the singularity.
If it is out there,
we need to locate it
and find a way
to get rid of it.
Right.
I wanted to let you know
I moved the Romulans
to different quarters.
Oh?
It's the
replicators again.
I assigned
a maintenance crew.
But in the meantime,
I moved the entire
Romulan delegation
to section 47, level 2
in the Habitat Ring.
Section 47?
Yes. Is something wrong?
The wall panel
where O'Brien saw
himself being killed
is right outside
those quarters.
( sighs )
Which means either the Romulans
are going to put a device
in the bulkhead themselves
or someone else will
possibly to be used
against the Romulans.
Should I move them
to other quarters?
No. That'll warn
whoever is responsible.
But inform Odo
of the change in quarters.
He already has that corridor
under surveillance.
Let's see how
this thing plays out
before we make
any further moves.
You have something,
Constable?
Someone has
planted a class-3
surveillance device
behind the wall panel
we've been monitoring.
Were you able
to see who it was?
No, we've been monitoring
the corridor constantly
for the past three hours.
No one's come anywhere
near the panel.
However, sensors
did detect
a low-energy
transporter beam
a short time ago.
They beamed the device
directly into the wall.
That's a delicate piece
of transporter work.
Yes, it is.
We haven't been able
to trace the beam
to its point of origin,
but since there aren't
any ships nearby,
I believe it originated
on the station.
Any suspects?
Since it appears
to be a device
intended to conduct
covert surveillance
of the Romulans,
my leading suspects
would be the Klingons.
Do you have any evidence
besides the fact
that Klingons hate Romulans?
Well, not yet,
but don't worry.
I plan to investigate
the Klingons
the Bajorans, Quark,
the visiting Terrellians...
You think Quark had
something to do with this?
I always investigate Quark.
Looks like you're going
to cheat death, after all.
Round about this time,
you saw yourself
being killed.
I feel like someone just
walked over my grave.
I mean, I've had a few brushes
with death in my career,
but there was something
about watching myself
being killed--
of feeling my own neck for
a pulse that wasn't there.
Well, could have
been worse.
Could have been me.
( chuckles )
Here you are, gentlemen.
And how is DS9's
most famous fortune teller?
Don't call me that.
I haven't told
anyone's fortune.
Oh, just a figure
of speech.
On the other hand,
if you should find yourself
in the future again,
and you find yourself
passing by the dabo table,
would it really hurt
to take a look
at the numbers
coming up on the wheel?
I could make it
worth your while.
Let's get
out of here.
Just a thought.
Can you believe that?
I'm being pulled
into the future,
and all he can
think about is...
Chief!
Oh, am I glad
to see you.
What the hell
happened to me, Julian?
It was the, the radiation.
I didn't realize it had
damaged the basilar arteries
in your brain stem
until it was too late.
Well, why not?
It didn't show up on
any of the diagnostics.
I couldn't tell
what had happened until
I was doing the autopsy.
Autopsy.
I just finished doing it
a few moments ago.
Do you want me
to show you the results?
No, no, no!
That's, that's all right.
Now, look, when you go
back to the past,
ask me to perform
a basilar arterial scan,
and since you're going
five hours back into the past
I should have enough time
to find the damage
and repair it before...
this happens.
Right.
How could you
just let me die?
I didn't just
let you die.
I did everything I could
to keep you alive
for over an hour,
but your body
just gave up.
Gave up?
I'm sorry, Chief.
But there comes a point
when the human body
just gives up.
Yeah, well, maybe
my Doctor wasn't...
Bashir to Infirmary.
I need a nurse and an emergency
medkit here immediately.
We finally were
able to localize
the transporter beam
and trace it back
to this location.
These quarters have
been vacant for weeks.
Somehow they overrode
the security lock on
the door to gain access.
So, what did they do?
Bring in a portable
transporter
and beam the
surveillance equipment
into the bulkhead?
That was
my first thought,
but then I realized that
a portable transporter
is a rather large and
bulky piece of equipment
to be carrying
around the halls.
That's true.
So...
then I began
thinking about...
the replicator.
Ah... they realigned
the matter-energy
conversion matrix.
Turning it into
a small transporter--
a very sophisticated,
very professional job.
So now we know
how they did it.
The next question is who.
I think I have the answer
to that as well.
Now, this device is manufactured
on Davlos III--
a planet on
the Klingon border.
ODO:
In fact, Davlos does
over 90 percent
of its trade
with the Klingon Empire.
Oh, that's still very little
evidence to make an arrest.
Yes, it is, but then
I contacted a friend at
Starfleet Intelligence
who used to be assigned
to the Federation Embassy
on the Klingon Homeworld.
He put me in contact
with a former
Klingon operative
who is out of favor
with the current
administration.
This former operative sent
me a series of reports...
Odo... cut to the chase.
The three Klingons
now on the station
are part of
a covert strike force
that reports directly
to the Klingon High Council.
Why didn't you just say so?
Well, sometimes I have
to remind you
just how good I am.
Mm. So, Gowron sent
our three friends here
and they're conducting
surveillance on the
Romulan delegation. Why?
Are they here to kill them?
Possibly.
It's also possible
that this is just
a routine intelligence-
gathering operation.
The high-energy laser
that killed O'Brien
is simply a booby trap
to prevent someone from
tampering with the device.
It's not meant
for assassination.
Well, in either case,
I think we have
enough evidence
to at least
hold the Klingons for
questioning, don't you?
Absolutely.
And I think I can
question them
until the Romulan delegation
leaves the station.
Just be careful.
Commander, there
is no careful way
to question a Klingon.
I have...
I haven't given up.
( panting )
I won't give up.
It's all right, Chief.
You're okay.
No, I'm not.
You need to run
a basilar arterial scan.
Why?
Because if you don't,
I'm going to die
in less than five hours.
Who told you that?
You did.
In the future.
Oh.
Well, who am I
to argue with me?
Let me go!
KLINGON:
This is an outrage.
We have
done nothing.
We will have our vengeance
on all of you for this.
You are treating us
with dishonor.
We have done
nothing wrong.
We take a very dim view of spies
and saboteurs on this station.
Now you slander us.
When my family finds out
what you have done,
they will come here
and kill you.
I doubt that very much.
The only people
who will be coming here
are your friends
in Klingon Intelligence.
And from what I understand,
they don't like being
embarrassed by operatives
who fail in their missions.
However, should you suddenly
feel like cooperating,
I may be persuaded
to let you go
without contacting your friends
in Intelligence.
Maybe.
So how are you feeling, Chief?
Better, sir.
I've eliminated almost all
the radioisotopes from his body.
Have to wait
a couple more hours
before I give him
the last treatment.
But after that,
there should be no more
time-shifting.
SISKO:
What about the
quantum singularity?
We've been able to track it
by using its tetryon
emissions as a guide.
It seems to be orbiting
Deep Space 9
in a roughly
elliptical fashion.
At certain points
in its orbit,
the singularity
radiates
temporal energy
at a specific wavelength.
That seems to be
what triggers my time shifts.
Is there any way
to break it out of its orbit
and send it on its way?
Well, we were
hoping to station...
( alarm blaring )
O'BRIEN: Come on,
come on. Hurry up.
We don't have much time!
Prepare to seal
the hatch
and release the
docking clamps.
MAN:
Move quickly.
Let's go.
All the way back.
Move quickly. Come on.
Initiating emergency
escape protocol.
Hang on,
I'm going to full impulse.
Now what?
You're here!
Look, I don't know
what happened.
I was asleep in bed when
the whole station was rocked
by an explosion.
Before I could get to Ops,
the evacuation alarm sounded.
And the com systems
were down.
O'BRIEN:
I got as many people
as I could in here.
I don't know what happened
to the others.
When you go back, you have
to find out what happened
and stop it.
My God!
Chief, what's wrong?
We've got a new problem, sir.
Did you see anything
from the runabout
that would indicate
how the station was destroyed?
There were a series
of explosions
that rippled across
the Habitat Ring.
But it all happened so fast,
I couldn't get a clear sense
of exactly what was going on.
Could you tell if you were
looking at internal explosions,
which might indicate some kind
of sabotage or accident,
or external explosions,
which might indicate
we were
under attack?
No. No, I'm not sure.
Do you remember seeing
any other ships nearby?
No, but I had a very limited
view of the area.
Well, it looks like,
at this point
we can't rule
anything out.
Agreed.
Make preparations
to evacuate the station.
Do it quietly.
If the destruction
of the station
is the result
of an attack or sabotage,
we don't want
to alarm our enemy
and make him trigger events
we're trying to avoid.
Begin a complete
systems check
of everything
on the station
that could potentially
cause this kind
of explosion.
Right.
O'BRIEN:
Commander...
there might be another way
to find out what's going on.
If I could travel
into the future again--
this time just before
the destruction of DS9--
I might be able to find out
what's going to happen,
then return to the present
in time for us to prevent it
from happening.
If you could flood
my body with high
concentrations
of delta-series
radioisotopes,
it might trigger
a time shift
into the future.
Possibly,
but those isotopes are toxic.
It could cause permanent damage
to your nervous system.
It might even kill you.
Well, if the future happens
the way I saw it happen,
a lot of people are
going to get killed
when the station
explodes.
It's a risk I'm willing to take.
SISKO:
Even if you're able to
initiate a time jump,
each time you traveled
into the future,
you've always gone five hours.
How do you propose to shorten
the length of a jump?
Well, there might be a link
between the temporal frequency
of the singularity
and the length
of the time shift.
We might be able
to calibrate
the decay constant
of the isotope that
we inject you with
to match the frequency
of the singularity.
And with a few
minor adjustments,
we can control
how far you jump
into the future.
Exactly.
All right.
But if you can't do it
within two hours,
I'm going to begin
to evacuate the station.
Understood.
Now, when you activate
this device,
it'll inject you with a two-rad
dose of delta isotopes.
Now, if our calculations
are right,
that should put you about
three hours into the future.
What's the margin
of error?
Plus or minus
half an hour, I'd say.
But that's the best
we could do.
It's already set
for the return trip.
So all you have to do is
activate it again to return
to the present.
Right.
And remember,
don't wait too long.
Your body will be experiencing
symptoms of severe
radiation poisoning.
If you don't get treatment,
it will kill you.
I won't forget.
Good.
Julian, there's a...
a message in my quarters
for Keiko if...
I understand, Miles.
0200.
That's three and a half hours
into the future.
Miles, Miles!
Wake up!
What?
Computer, lights.
Oh, no, not you again.
What is it now?
Listen to me.
I've jumped ahead
and seen your future.
Don't ask me how,
it'll take too long to explain.
There's going to be a disaster.
DS9 will be destroyed.
Destroyed? How?
I don't know.
That's why I'm here.
I have to find out
what's going to happen
and then travel back
into the past and prevent it.
You look pretty bad.
It's the radiation.
Well, if you feel bad
and you're my past self,
shouldn't
I feel bad, too?
BOTH:
I hate temporal mechanics.
Let's get down to Ops
and see what's going on.
( groaning )
Help me up.
Run a sensor sweep
of the entire station.
Look for anything
that might indicate a...
Report!
A Romulan warbird just
de-cloaked off of Lower Pylon 2.
They've taken out
our shield generators.
On screen.
Lock phasers and return fire.
( groans )
They've hit the fusion reactor.
Main power's down.
Defense systems
off-line.
Try to reroute phasers
through the emergency
power couplings.
Miles, you've got
your answer.
The quantum singularity that's
been orbiting the station--
it's the Romulans.
Are you listening?
The Romulans use
a confined singularity
to power their warp core.
That's what we've
been detecting.
That's what's causing
the time shifts.
You must go back
and tell them
to put up the shields
and stand by
for an attack.
I can't.
I can't get through
another shift.
It's the radiation poisoning,
it...
You go.
Just activate it.
It's set for
the return trip.
Me?
I don't belong there.
I'm you... you're me...
It does... doesn't matter.
Just go.
Go!
( explosion )
Chief! What happened?
It worked.
O'Brien to Sisko.
SISKO:
Go ahead, Chief.
I've been to the
future, Commander.
The quantum singularity
off the station
is actually
in the warp core
of a cloaked
Romulan warbird.
They're going to de-cloak
and fire on us
in a matter of hours.
Understood, Chief.
Raise shields.
Stand by weapons systems.
I don't
understand it.
Your body
should be flooded
with delta-series
radiation,
but there's only a tiny
amount in your tissues.
Your metabolic readings
are different.
What happened?
There's been a...
a change.
Uh... I really have
nothing else to say.
I think you're lying, Quark.
About what part?
All of it.
Well, at least
I'm consistent.
( laughs )
Quark, you can leave.
Thank you.
I know you have a cloaked
warbird orbiting the station.
And I know that you're
planning an attack.
At first, I couldn't
understand why,
and then I remembered
what you said about
the Dominion--
how they were the greatest
threat to the Alpha Quadrant
in the last century.
If you really
believed that,
then the only way you
could ever be truly safe
from the Dominion would be
to collapse the wormhole.
But you knew we wouldn't
just sit by
and watch while you did it.
So you had to destroy
the station, too.
That way, there'd
be no witnesses.
Everyone would assume that
Deep Space 9 was destroyed
by what appeared to be
the accidental collapse
of the wormhole.
An interesting...
theory, Commander.
But that's all it is,
a theory.
That's right.
But I'll tell you
what's not a theory.
We tracked the tetryon emissions
back to your warbird
and I have about
50 photon torpedoes
locked onto it right now.
I think it's time we left.
I couldn't agree more.
Constable, will you please
escort our... guests
to the nearest
transporter room?
If you'll
come with me.
So you're telling me
that you remember
playing this game
with me in the future?
Right.
All right, what am I
going to hit?
20, outer ring.
Why, that's remarkable.
It's also a little disturbing.
I have this nagging feeling
that I don't really belong here.
This isn't really my life.
You know, maybe this life
belongs
to that other Miles O'Brien.
Listen, Chief, whether you
are living in the past
or the present,
you are Miles O'Brien.
The only difference is,
you have a few memories
the other one didn't have.
Well, I think I'll go to bed.
I'm still kind of tired.
Now, that sounds
like a good idea.
Quark.
Dabo.
Dabo?
PLAYERS:
Dabo!
( excited cheering )
Wait, Chief, wait!
( laughs )