But I'm sorry, Doctor.
I just don't see the value
of this man's work.
But, Garak, Shakespeare
is one of the giants
of human literature.
I knew Brutus was going
to kill Caesar in the first act.
But Caesar didn't figure it out
until the knife was in his back.
But that's what makes it
a tragedy.
Caesar couldn't conceive
that his best friend
would plot to kill him.
"Tragedy" is not the word
I'd use.
"Farce" would be
more appropriate.
No, no, supposedly this man
is supposed to be a leader
of a great empire
a brilliant military tactician,
and yet he can't see
what's going on
under his own nose.
Hmm.
Doctor, are you in a hurry?
I have to get to the Infirmary.
I've got a lot of work
to do this afternoon.
Oh, you're fortunate.
I have more time
on my hands
than I know what to do with.
Maybe you could finish
those trousers
I dropped off last week.
Uh, tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
You're going to give
yourself indigestion.
Well, I only have you
to thank for that.
If you hadn't been so late,
I could have enjoyed my lunch.
Well, this isn't the first time
I've seen you
rush through a meal.
You never take the time
to savor your food.
It seems to be
a human characteristic.
Look over there.
That Talarian
is barely halfway
through his meal
but his human companion's
plate is empty.
Well maybe he and I
can have dessert
while you and the Talarian
while away the afternoon.
But it is a very interesting
sociological phenomenon
don't you think?
For generations now, humankind
has had more than enough food
and yet, you go about your
eating as if you were afraid
someone was going to come along
and snatch away your plate.
Garak, why don't you eat
for a while and let me talk?
Fear of starvation amid plenty.
It points to some dark secret
hidden in the human soul
a gnawing hunger.
Perhaps someone
should do a study.
Why don't you?
You appear to have
plenty of time on your hands.
Doctor, if you want
to have your dessert
please, go ahead.
I won't be offended.
I have to go
and I'm sorry to leave
while you're still eating.
No, no, I'm done as well.
But you've hardly
touched your plate.
If you really must know,
I've been nibbling
on Delavian chocolates
all morning.
Where did you get
Delavian chocolates?
Well, I promised my supplier
I wouldn't tell
but since I deprived you
of your dessert
I'd be more than happy to bring
some by the Infirmary
later this afternoon.
Why, thank you.
I'd like that.
Until then, Doctor?
Uh, Julian.
Major.
Garak.
About those atmospheric
specifications
you requested
for the Yalosian Ambassador...
60 percent nitrogen,
10 percent benzene
and the rest hydrogen
fluoride, as I recall.
Well we ran a test in one
of the guest quarters.
The mixture is so corrosive
it dissolved the carpet.
Well, don't look at me.
It's what they breathe.
Oh, then I guess we'll just
have to rip out the carpets.
Be sure not to replace them
with anything red or orange.
Why not?
They don't see that part
of the color spectrum.
Is there anything else
I should know
about the Yalosians?
As a matter of fact...
Bashir to Infirmary.
Medical emergency
on the Promenade.
It's Garak's shop.
Oh...
Are you all right?
As well as can be expected.
But I'm afraid your pants won't
be ready tomorrow after all.
Report.
The explosion was caused
by a rupture in the power
conduit behind that wall.
What caused the rupture?
Well, probably an overload
in the ODN juncture.
I take it you don't agree.
Well, let's just say,
I find it odd
that a conduit running
behind Garak's shop
should just happen to overload.
So you think someone
ruptured it deliberately?
I wouldn't be surprised.
It stands to reason that a man
with Garak's past
would have enemies.
I'm detecting traces
of nitrilin.
Nitrilin is extremely unstable.
And very rare.
It couldn't have come
from the power conduit.
This could be the residue
from a micro-explosive device
planted on the conduit
and rigged to cause a rupture.
Making the explosion
look like an accident.
Exactly.
Hmm.
Sisko to Ops.
Go ahead, Commander.
Delay the departure
of all vessels
until further notice.
I have reason to believe
that someone may have tried
to kill Mr. Garak.
Who would want to kill me,
a simple tailor?
A simple tailor.
A simple tailor
who used to be an agent
of the Obsidian Order.
The Obsidian Order.
Constable, you shouldn't
put too much stock
in the good Doctor's
flights of fancy.
Now, are you sure this explosion
wasn't an accident?
Because I can't think of anyone
who would wish me harm.
Someone tried to kill you,
Garak.
Whoever it was may try again,
so if I were you
I would give this matter
some serious thought.
Well, let me see.
I mean, there's the Nausicaan
whose wedding suit I misplaced
and the Yridian I owe money to
and of course,
there's always Major Kira.
This is serious, Garak.
I'm being serious.
I don't think she likes me.
She doesn't, but if she
wanted you dead, you would be.
You do have a point.
Could this attempt on your life
have anything
to do with the reason
you were exiled from Cardassia?
Oh, I seriously doubt
the Finance Ministry
would try to have me killed
for failure to pay my taxes.
You expect us to believe that's
the reason you were exiled?
Do you think I would lie
about a thing like that?
It's not something I'm proud of.
I don't like explosions
going off on my station, Garak.
Innocent people
could have been hurt.
You could have been killed.
Now if there's anything you know
you're not telling us
I suggest you start talking.
I've told you everything
I can think of.
All right, then.
I'll investigate
the "leads" you've given us.
If there's anyone else
you think I should
talk to, let me know.
I certainly will.
We've assigned
a security detail to you.
I suggest you stay
as close to them as possible.
Ah.
Someone should do a study.
A study?
To try and figure out
why some people
can't bring themselves
to trust anyone
even if it's
in their own best interest.
Why is it no one
ever believes me
even when I'm
telling the truth?
Have you ever heard
the story about the boy
who cried wolf?
No.
It's a children's story
about a young shepherd boy
who gets lonely
while tending his flock
so he cries out to the villagers
that a wolf is
attacking the sheep.
The people come running
but of course, there's no wolf.
He claims that it's run away
and the villagers praise him
for his vigilance.
Clever lad.
Charming story.
I'm not finished.
The next day,
the boy does it again
and the next, too
and on the fourth day,
a wolf really comes.
The boy cries out
at the top of his lungs
but the villagers ignore him
and the boy and his flock
are gobbled up.
Well, that's a little graphic
for children
wouldn't you say?
But the point is,
if you lie all the time
nobody's going to believe you
even when you're
telling the truth.
Are you sure
that's the point, Doctor?
Of course.
What else could it be?
That you should never
tell the same lie twice.
You wanted to see me?
I have bad news for you.
Major Kira has
an airtight alibi.
I thought you might want
to look over
the passenger manifests
of ships that recently
came to the station.
To see if I recognize anyone
who might wish me harm?
Exactly.
I suggest
you start
with the most recent arrivals
and work your way backwards.
Well, don't worry about me,
Constable.
I can manage on my own.
I'm not about to leave you
alone in here
so you can look through
my security files.
What makes you think
I haven't already
looked through them?
I'm joking, of course.
Of course.
No, I'm afraid I don't
recognize any of these names.
The bomb could have
been planted
days ago or even weeks.
I suggest you keep going back
just to be sure.
Oh, well,
this could take forever.
I should think
you'd have plenty
of time on your hands
now that your shop is
no longer open for business.
Hmm.
Odo, I...
I finished running
the bio-molecular scan
you asked me for.
I found traces of living tissue
on the bulkhead
around the blast site.
This looks like the remains
of a pheromonic sensor.
A what?
It's triggered
when a person of a particular
species gets within range.
In this case, a Cardassian.
Me.
They're known to be favored
by Flaxian assassins
and it just so happens
a Flaxian came aboard
the station just this morning.
So, Mister... Retaya
your papers indicate
that you're a merchant.
I deal in fine wares,
mostly fabrics and fragrances.
According to my information
you were a suspect in the murder
of Dekora Assan on Japori II.
I was cleared on those charges.
It was a case
of mistaken identity.
This is your sample case,
I take it.
Yes.
Well, how fortunate.
As it happens
I'm looking for a gift
for a friend.
A lady friend?
Exactly.
Unfortunately, I don't
have a sense of smell.
Perhaps you could describe
this fragrance for me.
It has a somewhat...
floral bouquet.
Hmm.
We have a Cardassian tailor
here on the station
named Garak.
There was an explosion
in his shop not long
after you arrived.
I felt the blast.
Was he hurt?
Not seriously.
Hmm?
That one is more musky
than the first.
Oh.
Tell me, where were you
when the explosion occurred?
The Ferengi's bar.
I went there as soon
as I arrived this morning.
Mm-hmm.
Huh?
I suppose I would have to
describe that one as... spicy.
Mm... I see.
And how long were you
at Quark's?
The rest of the day.
Right up until your Deputy
came and brought me here.
So, have you found something
for your lady friend?
Almost.
I think she would like
something both floral...
and musky.
Perhaps...
if we mixed these two?
Why not?
Very nice.
But on the other hand
she's also quite fond
of spicy things.
Maybe we could add...
a drop of this as well.
I really don't think
they would go well together.
Let's find out.
I really don't think your lady
friend will like the aroma.
Much less the fact that
when these three fragrances
are combined
they produce a gaseous mixture
that can trigger a fatal heart
attack when inhaled.
I had no idea.
Then why did you stop me
from mixing them?
As I said
I simply didn't think your
friend would like the aroma.
Unless you have any more
questions, I'd like to go now.
I have deliveries to make
on Cardassia.
I'll let you know when you
can leave the station.
Everything's set.
The transponder is on board
the Flaxian's ship.
You're sure he won't find it?
Not a chance.
I've hidden it inside
the ship's magneton relay.
You'll be able to track him
as long as you stay
within half a light year.
Who do you think
he's going to lead you to?
If I knew that, I wouldn't
have to follow him.
Oh, I was wondering
when you'd get here.
The Flaxian left
two minutes ago.
If we're going to follow him,
we'd better get moving.
What makes you think
I'm going to follow him?
I happen to know
that you're too dogged
an investigator to allow
the only witness in this case
to simply disappear.
Oh, congratulations.
Your powers of deduction
are truly astonishing.
Now if you will kindly disembark
I will get on
with my dogged investigation.
I intend to go with you.
Forgive me...
but are you making a joke?
Cardassian humor escapes me.
I'm quite serious.
Believe me, when someone
tries to kill you
it's no laughing matter.
Perhaps, but I don't
require your company
on this trip.
My presence
could be most helpful.
Especially if the Flaxian
goes into Cardassian space.
I am not interested
in debating
your usefulness to me.
I hate to interrupt you
but the Flaxian
is getting farther away.
Now, I assume you've placed
a tracking device on his ship
but if we don't get started soon
he's going to get out of range.
Rio Grande to Ops.
Request permission to depart.
Permission granted.
Trust me, Constable
I can be a most pleasant
traveling companion.
And this promises to be
an interesting trip.
The tracking device
is working perfectly.
If I'm reading this correctly...
and I'm no expert...
it looks like the Flaxian ship
is about to go into warp.
Well... it seems
that our "interesting trip"
has just been cut short.
According to our sensor logs,
the Flaxian ship exploded
the moment its warp
drive was engaged.
Was there malfunction?
Well, that's what I thought
at first.
Then I analyzed the telemetry
from the transponder
I planted on board
the Flaxian ship.
Just before the explosion
there was
an interference pattern
in the transponder's signal.
This interference
could have been caused
by a forced neutrino inversion.
The Romulans.
They use neutrino inverters
in their explosive devices.
Why would the Romulans want
to destroy the Flaxian's ship?
One possibility
is that the Romulans hired
the Flaxian to kill Garak
and then killed the Flaxian
when he failed in his mission.
Do you have any evidence
to support that?
It's only a supposition,
but it fits the available facts.
All right, Mr. Garak.
Do you know why the Romulans
might hire someone to kill you?
I have no idea.
I'm getting tired
of hearing you say that.
How long do you expect us
to believe...
He's telling the truth,
Commander.
He doesn't know why the Romulans
would try to kill him.
What makes you so sure?
Because if he did know,
he'd already be spinning out
an elaborate web of lies
to cover up the truth.
Well, the truth
is usually just an excuse
for lack of imagination.
Is it?
If you want to know what
the Romulans have against me
you'll have to ask them.
I intend to
but I don't expect them
to be entirely forthcoming.
Yes, we destroyed
the Flaxian's ship.
I have to say
I'm a little surprised
to hear you admit it so easily.
Why would we hide it?
Retaya was wanted for crimes
against the Romulan Empire.
His execution
was perfectly legal.
We have information
that he may have worked
as an assassin.
I have nothing
to corroborate that
though it wouldn't surprise me.
Well, shortly
after he arrived here
someone tried
to kill a Cardassian
who lives aboard this station.
That would be Mr. Garak...
a cobbler, I believe.
A tailor, actually.
I'll correct our records.
That is, if he's still alive.
He is.
Well.
Is there anything else?
One more thing.
How long had the Tal Shiar
been looking for Retaya?
Nearly a year. Why?
Isn't it curious
that you finally
caught up with him here
just hours after he attempted
to kill Mr. Garak?
We're just grateful
to have found him at all.
Now, if you're finished,
Commander
I have other matters
to attend to.
Hmm!
I take it you don't
believe her either?
No.
But the question still remains.
Why would the Romulans
want to have Garak killed?
I don't know.
Considering those uniforms
of theirs, you'd think
they'd appreciate
a decent tailor.
So, where does this leave
your investigation?
At a standstill.
We don't know that the
Romulans hired the Flaxian.
We don't even know
that it was Retaya
who tried to kill Garak.
All we do know is
that a bomb went off
in Garak's shop.
All right...
then let's start with him.
What do we know about Garak?
He was exiled from Cardassia,
for what reason, we're not sure.
He never leaves the station.
He avoids contact
with other Cardassians.
And it's possible
that he was once an intelligence
agent of the Obsidian Order.
A very strong possibility,
Commander.
Agreed.
So we can assume
that this attempt on his life
had something
to do with the Order.
Unfortunately, he's rather
uncooperative when it comes
to answering questions
about his past.
And the Obsidian Order
is uncooperative
when it comes
to answering questions
about their former agents.
Ordinarily, yes.
What do you mean?
I have certain resources
in the Cardassian government.
I take it you don't want
to elaborate on that?
I'd rather not.
But I would like to request
the use of a runabout.
Granted.
Thank you, sir.
Stop there.
Where are you?
Nearby.
I've changed my appearance
since last we saw each other.
I don't want you to see me.
I need some information.
Is this about the tailor shop?
Yes.
I didn't do it.
I wasn't going to ask you that.
I think the Romulans
tried to kill Garak.
Very good, Odo.
I see working for the Bajorans
hasn't entirely dulled
your instincts.
My question is, "why?"
You'd have to ask the Romulans.
But I do know
that you are investigating
a very insignificant piece
of a much larger puzzle.
What do you mean?
There's been a great deal
of unusual
Romulan activity
these past weeks.
Cloaked ships believed
to be warbirds
have been detected near
the Cardassian border...
troop movements...
communication activity...
Sounds like they're
preparing for an invasion.
It has occurred to us
and we're ready for it,
if it should happen.
But it doesn't make any sense.
Does war ever make sense?
Still the wry observer
of humanoid folly.
Tell me, do you still do
the Cardassian neck trick?
No, I don't.
Pity.
You were so good at it.
Garak isn't the only former
operative in the Order
who had an "unfortunate
incident" yesterday
but he's the luckiest.
The other five didn't survive.
Five operatives were
killed yesterday?
"Killed"?
No.
Three died from "natural causes"
the other two perished
in "accidents."
Quite a coincidence.
If you believe in coincidence.
I take it you think
the Romulans
had something to do
with their deaths?
There were certain indications
of their involvement.
That still leaves us
with the question, "why?"
Here.
Those are the names
of the five dead operatives.
I suggest you show that to Garak
then ask him that question.
I'll do that.
I trust you'll agree
that this information
satisfies my debt to you.
Agreed.
However, if you
do learn something
from your tailor,
and wish to share it with me
I would be indebted
to you again.
I'll consider it.
They're all dead?!
I take it you're not going
to mourn their passing?
Oh, quite the contrary!
In fact, if these were
different circumstances
I'd be celebrating tonight.
So you did know them?
Oh, yes, we were
quite well-acquainted.
In the Obsidian Order?
Oh, Constable, we've been
down this road before.
I don't see why...
I've had enough
of your dissembling, Garak!
I am not Dr. Bashir
and we are not sparing
amiably over lunch!
Now you dragged me
into this investigation
and you are now going
to cooperate with me!
"Dragged you in"?
I don't know
what you're talking...
You blew up your own shop,
Garak!
Well...
I don't think I've ever seen
that particular expression
on your face.
Is it surprise?
Yes, Constable, it is.
I'm surprised that you
could come to this
unlikely conclusion.
Oh, drop the pretense.
I knew as soon as I spoke
with the Flaxian.
Assassins don't like
varying their methods.
He planned to poison you.
I think you spotted
him on the station
and then blew up your own shop
so that I'd begin
an investigation.
That seems like
a very elaborate way
to get you involved.
If I needed your help
I could have just asked.
But you couldn't be sure
that I'd take you seriously,
or that I'd help you.
Besides, I think
you secretly enjoyed
destroying your own shop.
Well, I admit watching it burn
wasn't exactly tragic.
Whether or not you
want to admit it
you pulled me into this case,
and now you're stuck with me.
I want to know
who those men were
and what your connection
was to them.
We were all associates
of Enabran Tain.
Enabran Tain, the former head
of the Obsidian Order.
He retired some years ago.
He was, I might add,
the only head of the agency
who ever lived
long enough to do so.
For some time, we were
his most trusted advisors.
Do you have
any idea why the Romulans
would want you all dead?
I don't know...
but Tain might.
That is unless he
suffered an "unfortunate
accident" as well.
That is a distinct possibility.
May I use
your communications system?
By all means.
Well, that's an interesting way
of scrambling a signal.
Yes, I thought you
might appreciate it
on an aesthetic level.
Ah, here we are.
Mila.
Elim.
I never thought
I'd see your face again.
I need to speak to Tain.
It's urgent.
You can't.
He isn't here.
Where is he?
I don't know.
He left yesterday
in a great hurry.
He wouldn't tell me where...
Maybe he realized
someone was coming after him.
He's in trouble, isn't he?
You have to help him, Elim.
I know you're still bitter
because of what happened
between the two of you, but...
you must help him, Elim.
If you speak to him,
tell him to contact me.
Promise me.
You help him.
I promise.
I'll need a runabout,
Constable.
We'll need a runabout.
I'm coming with you.
I hope you know
what you're doing, Garak.
So do I.
Is there anything you need
me to do while you're gone?
Like what?
I don't know...
any unfinished business?
Actually, Doctor,
there is something.
Well, what?
If you go into my quarters
and examine the bulkhead
next to the replicator
you'll notice
there's a false panel.
Behind that panel,
is a compartment
containing an isolinear rod.
If I'm not back
within 78 hours
I want you to take that rod
and eat it.
Eat it?
Mm-hmm.
You're joking.
Yes, Doctor, I am.
Very funny.
I thought so.
But the answer to your question,
Doctor, is "no."
There's nothing you can do
for me while I'm away.
Then these are for you.
Delavian chocolates.
But these were meant for you.
I know... I thought
you might need them
more than I do.
Thank you.
Good luck.
Hmm.
We've cleared the station.
Now if you'll be kind enough
to let me know where we're
going, I'll set a course.
Head for the Cardassian border.
We're going to the third planet
of the Unefra system.
How do you know
that's where Tain has gone?
I don't, but he has
a safe house there
that no one's supposed
to know about...
especially me.
That woman, Mila...
who is she?
She's been Tain's housekeeper
and confidant for over 30 years.
She seemed almost fond of you.
Is it so hard to believe
that there's one person
in this galaxy
who could regard me
with a certain affection?
Well, I could believe
there's one
but I wouldn't expect it
to be someone who worked
for Enabran Tain.
As I understand it
the two of you didn't part
on the best of terms.
You could say that.
Tain was directly responsible
for my exile from Cardassia.
Then I don't understand...
Why I would be risking my life
to help him?
Exactly.
Yes...
I can see
how that would be puzzling.
All right...
you owe him something.
Ha!
A logical deduction.
I see why you're the Constable.
But it's more than that.
He means something to you.
Something personal?
Ah, now you've just moved
from deduction to supposition.
You're not the kind of man
who would go to such lengths
simply to repay a debt.
Are you trying to say that
I have no sense of honor?
Well, that remains to be seen.
Yes.
You wouldn't risk going
into Cardassian space
for just anyone.
It would have to be someone
important to you...
someone you cared about.
I think you were more
than Tain's advisor.
I think you were his protégé
and he was your mentor.
That is, until he sent you
into exile.
And yet, despite all that
you care enough about him
to risk your life for him.
Or is all that just supposition?
Very interesting analysis...
very interesting.
Particularly coming from you.
Oh?
It's been my observation
that you always act
from a sense of justice
or at least,
what you consider justice.
There's no feeling
behind what you do...
no emotion beyond
a certain distaste
for loose ends and disorder.
You don't know what it means
to care about someone, do you?
People are just
interesting creatures
to be studied and analyzed.
Is there any point to this?
Only that I find it
interesting
that you ascribe feelings
and motivations to me
that you know nothing about.
Or am I wrong?
Tell me.
Is there one person in this
universe you do care for?
One person who's more
than just an interesting
puzzle to be solved.
Is there, Odo?
Anyone?
If there were, I certainly
wouldn't tell you.
And that would be
a wise decision.
I'm taking us out of warp.
We're approaching
the Unefra system.
What's that?
I'm detecting
a subspace energy surge
directly above us.
A vessel of some kind
is de-cloaking.
It's a Romulan warbird.
In Cardassian space?
They've locked onto us
with a tractor beam.
Take the helm.
I'll going to try to send out
a distress signal.
I can't pull away.
The tractor lock is too strong.
They're jamming
our transmission.
Do you think you got through?
I don't know.
I'm going to hail them,
see what they want.
I think we're about to find out.
Tain.
Ah, Garak, it's good
of you to come.
It spares me the trouble
of having to send
someone else to kill you.
Come in, come in!
It's been a long time, Elim.
So, you're a tailor now.
Is this one of your creations?
A minor example of my work, yes.
I don't think
I like the neckline.
Well, you always did have
a keen sense of fashion
but you seem to have let it go
along with your
once-trim figure.
Constable Odo.
I've always wanted to meet you.
I wish I could say the same.
Oh, come now.
Haven't you ever been the
least bit curious about me
about my relationship
with Garak
or our work
in the Obsidian Order?
I seldom waste time
speculating
about retired spymasters
and their associates.
He's good.
He hides his true feelings
almost as well as you do, Elim.
He'd have made a good
operative in the old days.
I had the same thought myself.
But then, those days
are long gone.
At least, they are for me.
You, on the other hand
seem to have left
your retirement far behind
unless you're simply
on a pleasure cruise
with your pointed-eared friends.
Cunning, isn't he?
He makes a racial slur
within earshot of two Romulans
putting me in the position
of either defending them
thus, giving away
my allegiance to them
or letting the comment pass...
in which case
he's managed to plant a seed
of discord between us.
Frankly, I don't find
any of this interesting.
You both go to such lengths
to hide the true meaning
of your words
you end up saying nothing.
I think you'll find
when I have something to say
you won't have any trouble
understanding it.
To answer your question,
Garak
no, I'm not
on a pleasure cruise.
This ship is part of a fleet
of Romulan
and Cardassian vessels.
A fleet that will
very soon be traveling
through the wormhole
into the Gamma Quadrant.
I take it you're not
on a mission
of peaceful exploration.
Not exactly.
You're going to attack
the Dominion, aren't you?
You're going to stage
a first strike against them
before they can come
into the Alpha Quadrant.
A clear and precise analysis.
Commander Sisko must find you
a valuable advisor.
A daring plan.
I didn't think there was anyone
in the Central Command
bold enough
to take on the Dominion.
Who said anything
about the Central Command?
This is a joint operation
between the Obsidian Order
and the Tal Shiar.
We've been building
a fleet of ships
in the Orias system
for months now.
If you attack the Dominion,
they'll certainly strike back.
You'll be taking Romulus
and Cardassia into war...
a war you may not win.
I don't think
they'll be striking back.
Our intention is
to wipe out the Dominion
in one single blow
by eliminating the Founders.
Without them, the Dominion
will collapse.
You seem disturbed
by this, changeling.
Why? After all...
didn't you turn your back
on your people?
You seem to know a great deal
about me and my people.
We know everything you know
including the location
of their homeworld.
Ah!
Starfleet has shared
their intelligence
on the Dominion
with the Romulans.
And the Romulans
have shared it with me.
You'll forgive me
if I reduce the scope
of this conversation
to something
a little more personal.
But why was it
necessary to kill me
and the rest of our
former colleagues
in order to embark
on this excursion
into the Gamma Quadrant?
Because, Garak, I don't plan
on going back into retirement
when this is over.
I plan on going back
to my old job and my old life.
You were afraid we knew things...
things that could
be used against you
and so you decided
to have us eliminated.
Like I used to say, always
burn your bridges behind you.
You never know who might be
trying to follow.
You always used to say, as well,
that the Tal Shiar was sloppy.
You never should have relied
on them to burn your bridges.
True.
They never should have hired
the Flaxian
to blow up your shop.
Actually, I blew up my shop.
It was a way
of piquing the interest
of the good Constable here.
You blew up your own shop?
You, my friend,
are a true original.
If you hadn't betrayed me
things would have been
very different.
I never betrayed you!
At least, not in my heart.
Why do you think I'm here?
I came because I thought
the Romulans were
trying to kill you.
I came here to save you.
I never thought I'd hear
myself say this, Garak...
but I believe you.
You can go.
Excuse me?
The changeling, of course,
will have to stay
but you're free to go.
Your runabout is
in Launching Bay 3.
Just like that?
Just like that.
Aren't you concerned
that I might warn
the Central Command
and Starfleet of your plans?
It's too late.
Central Command will have
a war on its hands
whether it wants one or not.
And as for Starfleet,
this isn't their fight.
They won't interfere.
It's a trick, Garak.
After all this, he won't
let you just walk away.
It's not a trick, it's a choice.
You can walk out
that door or join me.
Join you?
That is what you've been
waiting for, isn't it?
To end your exile?
To come back into the fold?
I'm asking you to serve
Cardassia again, by my side.
You'll pardon me if I appear
a little startled
but are you saying
that all is forgiven?
I can't forgive what you did,
but I can try to forget...
to put it aside
as if it never happened.
So, do you want to go back
to your shop and hem pants
or shall we pick up
where we left off?
Garak, this is the man
who put you into exile.
This is the man
who just two days ago
tried to have you killed.
Yes, he is...
but it doesn't matter.
I am back.