Last time on
Deep Space Nine...
Bashir to Infirmary.
Medical emergency
on the Promenade.
I find it odd that
a conduit running
behind Garak's shop
should just happen
to overload.
Why would the Romulans want
to destroy the Flaxian's ship?
One possibility
is that the Romulans hired
the Flaxian to kill Garak
and then killed the Flaxian
when he failed
in his mission.
Do you know why
the Romulans might hire
someone to kill you?
I have
no idea.
MALE:
You are investigating
a very insignificant piece
of a much larger puzzle.
What do you mean?
There's been a great deal
of unusual Romulan activity
these past weeks.
You dragged me
into this investigation,
and you are now going
to cooperate with me!
"Dragged you in"?
I don't know what
you're talking...
You blew up
your own shop, Garak!
ODO:
It's a Romulan warbird.
In Cardassian space?
You're going to
attack the Dominion,
aren't you?
You're going to stage
a first strike against them
before they can come
into the Alpha Quadrant.
I'm asking you to serve
Cardassia again, by my side.
Garak, this is the man
who put you into exile.
This is the man
who just two days ago
tried to have you killed.
Yes, he is...
but it doesn't matter.
I am back.
And now, the conclusion.
BASHIR: I mean,
if you ask me
modern theater
has been on
the decline since
the late 23rd century.
I mean, just look
at the plays to have
come out of Earth
in the last 50 years,
and compare them
to the works of Willemheld
or Barton or Chow-yun.
Yes, yes!
Modern playwrights
have become obsessed
with writing human
interpretations of
alien theatrical works
while ignoring completely
our own unique
cultural heritage.
In the hopes of...
Chief?
Are you
listening to me?
What?
I thought so.
Oh.
Oh, I-I heard
every word you said.
And what do you think?
About what?
Any of it.
I...
don't know.
Look, what do you
want me to say?
Say you agree,
or say you disagree.
Say you hate theater.
Just say something.
Look, Julian, you said
you wanted to have lunch.
Well, we're having lunch.
Yes! But I was hoping
for a little more conversation
with my plomeek soup.
Ah, my mother taught me
if you try to combine
talking and eating,
you'll end up doing neither
very well.
Well, I suppose Garak taught me
to think of lunch
as a sort of arena
for philosophical debate.
I take it there's still no word
about Garak and Odo?
The Starship Portland
and a Cardassian cruiser
are still searching the Algira
sector for the runabout.
Well, that's not
entirely bad news.
If the runabout
had been destroyed,
they would have
found debris by now
or something to...
Kira to O'Brien.
Go ahead, Major.
Report to Ops, Chief.
There's something here we'd
like you to take a look at.
On my way.
SISKO: About ten minutes ago
our sensors picked up
high concentrations
of tetryon particles
moving toward the station.
I've never seen
readings like these.
What do you think?
Subspace energy
fluctuations?
Quantum fractures
in the electrodynamic
field?
EM spikes across
the spectrum?
You've got me.
Whatever it is,
it's getting closer.
And larger.
The tetryon concentrations
have increased ten percent
in the last 30 seconds.
There's an energy surge,
bearing 210 mark 315.
A ship is de-cloaking.
It's a Romulan warbird.
Romulans?
Open a channel...
Another warbird
is de-cloaking at 010...
No, it's a Cardassian ship.
A Cardassian ship
with a cloaking device?
Definitely Cardassian,
Keldon-class.
Benjamin, there's an entire
fleet de-cloaking out there.
Red Alert! All hands
to battle stations.
Shields up!
Stand by weapons.
Try to hail them,
Lieutenant.
Their weapons are charged,
but they haven't
locked on to us yet.
Lead ship's headed for
the wormhole, Commander.
No response to our hails.
The fleet's following
the lead ship.
They're headed for
the Gamma Quadrant.
Lieutenant, open
a priority channel
to Starfleet Command now.
You should have seen the look
on Legate Porania's face
when I told him I was going
into retirement three years ago.
He was literally speechless--
a rare event.
I remember wanting to invent
charges of treason
against him
just so I wouldn't have
to hear his voice again.
And you would have, too,
if I hadn't held you back.
You had quite a vicious
streak in those days.
Oh, I learned...
from the best.
No, no,
you had a gift.
I never met anyone else
who relished a good
interrogation
as much as you did.
Do you remember getting
that confession
out of Dr. Parmak?
I never even touched him.
That was
the beauty of it.
You just sat there
for, what?
Three hours?
Four!
And after four hours
of watching you
stare at him,
he confessed.
( chuckles ):
I was good, wasn't I?
You were brilliant.
Afterwards,
he just kept saying,
"His eyes...
his eyes."
I've missed you, Elim.
Things just haven't been
the same since you left.
I've missed you,
too, Enabran.
We're both getting
sentimental
in our old age.
Hmm.
Next thing you know,
we'll be crying
over our lost youth.
So, whatever happened
to Dr. Parmak?
He spent three years
in a labor camp,
then returned
to Cardassia Prime.
I think he's practicing
medicine again.
When we get back,
you should look him up.
Oh, there are a number
of people I intend to
look up when we get back.
For instance,
do you remember
a Gul named Dukat?
Dukat?
Oh, yes, the business
with the arms merchants.
Mm-hmm.
I take it you'd like
to have him eliminated.
The thought had
crossed my mind.
When this mission
is completed,
you'll be in a position to
eliminate anyone you want.
I'll make up a list
and give it to Mila.
Perhaps you'd better
give it to me personally.
Mila may not be
around much longer.
She knows a great deal about me,
too much for her own good.
Well, still, it would be
a shame to have her killed.
She's proven that she can be
trusted on numerous occasions,
and you'd be hard put
to find a better housekeeper.
Is this a request I hear?
Not at all.
Just an observation.
No reason to pretend, Garak.
You're fond of Mila.
You don't want
her hurt, right?
If you're looking
for an excuse
to spare the life
of your own housekeeper,
you don't need me
to provide you with one.
You can do it out
of the kindness of your heart.
Mila always believed
you were innocent
of betraying Cardassia...
and me.
I was.
Of course.
No wonder the Romulans
can't conquer the galaxy.
No one can stomach
their cuisine.
( door opening )
TAIN:
Ah, Colonel Lovok.
Allow me to introduce
my associate, Elim Garak.
And what is his role to be
in this operation?
He will do whatever
I require of him.
Elim is
a cherished colleague
of long standing.
He will not enter the Bridge
or any other secured space
aboard this ship unescorted.
If you do so,
you will be killed.
Direct, isn't he?
I'm afraid
the Colonel believes
in wasting little time
on pleasantries
or idle conversation.
The fleet is re-cloaked
and is about to set course
for the Founders' homeworld
at warp six.
GARAK:
Warp six?
That's a bit slow,
isn't it?
Something wrong
with your engines?
If we travel any faster,
our warp signatures may be
detected by the Jem'Hadar,
even through
the cloaking devices.
Very clever.
The changeling is
in quarters on C deck.
There are force fields
in place to prevent his escape.
Good. Which brings us
to your first
assignment, Garak.
I want you to
explain to Odo
that it would be
in everyone's
best interest--
especially his-- if
he were to provide us
with all the information
he has on his people.
Now, that might
prove difficult.
He can be quite stubborn.
Then you'll have
to find a way
of convincing him.
( door opening )
Well, Odo, I trust
the accommodations
meet with your approval.
( snorts )
Well, you have to admit
it's certainly better
than a prison cell.
There are force fields
around the bulkheads
and a guard outside the door.
Feels like a prison cell to me.
I see your point.
And believe me, if it were
my decision, things would...
I don't believe you, Garak,
and I doubt I'll believe
much of what you have
to say from now on.
So save us both some trouble
and leave me alone.
Why, Constable, you seem
positively disappointed in me.
Well, I suppose
it's understandable.
After all, I did pledge
my undying devotion
and eternal allegiance
to both you and the Federation.
And you and I have been
through so much together--
shared many experiences--
and I know you considered me
a close friend.
No wonder you
feel betrayed.
You're wasting
your time, Garak.
I don't care about
the rationalizations
you come up with
to justify your actions.
To justify? I don't
need to justify
anything to you.
Living on Deep Space 9
has made you a little rusty.
Your lies are becoming
more transparent.
You should be careful.
You don't want Tain to know
that you're feeling guilty
about what you've done.
You are
imaginative, I'llgrant
you that, Constable,
but I would suggest that
you put those creative
powers to better use.
We would like you to share
your unique insights
on the Founders.
Would you?
We would be grateful--
most grateful--
for any information
you could provide.
And if I refuse?
Oh, really, Odo.
You really must stop reading
those human crime novels
Chief O'Brien gives you.
It's poisoning your thinking.
I'm not here to threaten you.
I just want to talk.
I don't feel like talking.
Surely, you can see that we
share a common enemy--
the Founders.
By cooperating,
you'll be helping
us provide security
for the entire
Alpha Quadrant.
The only common enemy
you and I share
is Enabran Tain.
The difference
between you and I
is that you don't know it.
I suggest that you think over
what I've said, Constable.
Funny, I was about to make
the same suggestion.
Since the Jem'Hadar
are genetically
addicted to a drug
that only the Founders
can provide,
we expect the Jem'Hadar
to weaken and die
once their supplies
of the drug run out.
A matter of days,
by our estimates.
However, that will give them
enough time to stage
some kind of counterattack
against the Alpha Quadrant.
So I suggest you place
the Cardassian fleet on alert.
I take this action
not in defiance
of the Cardassian state,
but in defense of it.
You in the Central Command
have neglected
the security of our people
and allowed peace with Bajor
and the Federation
to blind you to the real threat,
the Dominion.
I intend to remove that threat.
Let history be my judge.
That message was intercepted
by a Federation outpost
earlier today.
A similar message was sent
to the Romulan Senate.
Now both governments
are denying
any prior knowledge
of Tain's plans
and calling this
a rogue operation.
Are they going to do
anything to stop Tain?
Both the Romulans
and the Cardassians
claim to be studying ways
to stop Tain.
But we believe
that they'll just sit back
and wait to see
if he succeeds or not.
But, sir, that could
plunge Romulus
and Cardassia into war
with the Dominion.
Only if he fails, Lieutenant.
His plan looks like it's got
a fair chance of success.
He's commanding
a fleet of 20 ships
manned by combat veterans.
They know the location
of the Founders' homeworld
and they've modified
their cloaks
so the Jem'Hadar
can't detect their approach.
It sounds like you're hoping
Tain will succeed.
I never hope for war, Major.
But if it comes,
I'd rather see the Dominion
on the losing side.
However, we have to plan
for the worst.
Ben, I want you to evacuate DS9
of all non-essential personnel
and put the Defiant
on standby alert.
Even if Tain succeeds,
the Jem'Hadar are going to come
screaming out of the wormhole
looking for revenge,
and they may not be
too particular
who their targets are.
Admiral, we believe
Security Chief Odo
is aboard one
of the Romulan ships.
Odo's message said
the runabout
had been caught
in a tractor beam.
That suggests
he was captured
and taken aboard
one of their ships.
SISKO: I'd like permission
to take the Defiant
into the Gamma Quadrant
and try to determine
if he's still alive.
I'm sorry about your officer,
but there's nothing we can do.
I want the Defiant
guarding Bajor.
That's your top priority.
Toddman out.
Commander Eddington,
am I correct in assuming
Starfleet is
planning to send
substantial reinforcements
to this sector?
Yes, sir.
A task force of nine starships
is due to arrive tomorrow.
Nine starships.
I want the Defiant
prepared to leave
for the Gamma Quadrant
in two hours.
Sir, Admiral Toddman's orders
were quite clear on...
I am not going to just
abandon one of my officers.
Toddman's concerned
about the defense of Bajor,
and so am I.
If we detect
a Jem'Hadar strike force
heading for the Alpha Quadrant,
we'll use the communications
relay to warn DS9.
And we'll do everything we can
to stop them before
they reach the wormhole.
I consider this
a volunteer mission,
but don't volunteer yet.
There's a good chance
you won't be coming back
from this mission.
And even if you do,
you'll probably be facing
a general court-martial.
If you do decide to go,
be aboard the Defiant
at 1530 hours.
Dismissed.
All stations report.
KIRA: Tactical ready.
O'BRIEN:
Warp and impulse
engines on line.
Cloaking device standing by.
DAX: Helm ready.
Security detachment
is aboard
and phaser rifles have been
issued to every fire team.
SISKO:
Release docking clamps.
Commander,
there's an incoming
priority message
from Starfleet Command.
It's Admiral Toddman.
He's repeating
his order
not to enter
the Gamma Quadrant.
That's what you
think it says.
How can you be sure
when a transmission is as
badly garbled as that one?
You're right.
There's an awful lot
of subspace interference
on this channel.
Must be an ion storm
or something.
Must be.
Aft thrusters,
back one-quarter.
Port and starboard
at station keeping.
The cloaking device
is operating within
normal parameters.
Set course for
the Founders' homeworld.
Warp eight.
LOVOK:
We know that the Founders'
planet lies
at approximately
these coordinates
within the Omarion Nebula.
As you can see, there are
no Jem'Hadar bases nearby.
This means that
even if the Founders
did send out
a distress call
it would take
at least seven hours
for any help to arrive.
Our plan is to wait
until we've entered orbit
of the Founders' planet,
then de-cloak and begin
massive bombardment.
LOVOK:
Computer analysis
indicates
that the planet's crust
will be destroyed
within one hour,
and the mantle within five.
Well, that should more than
take care of the Founders.
Yes, it should.
Unless they have some
planetary defenses
we don't know about.
There is one person here
who might answer
that question-- Mr. Odo.
Anything he knows
about the Founders
and their planet
was undoubtedly included
in his report to Starfleet.
The Constable is
remarkably thorough
in these matters.
There was a time when
you were eager to begin
an interrogation, Elim.
In fact, I remember having
to restrain your enthusiasm
on several occasions.
Well, then you should
also remember the pride
I took in my work.
I don't think that
interrogating someone who
can alter their form at will
is likely to provide either
amusement or information.
I wouldn't worry about Mr. Odo's
shape-shifting, if I were you.
The Obsidian Order
has developed a device
which should prove quite
effective in neutralizing him.
I was not informed
about this device.
It's only a prototype.
We've never had
a chance to test it...
until now.
Perhaps the Tal Shiar
should take over
the interrogation
of the changeling.
No.
It's all right, Garak.
It's my fault.
I should have known
you'd develop feelings
for these people
you've been living with
for the past few years.
But I just never expected
that you would become friends
with someone who worked
for the Bajorans.
This has nothing to do with
my friends or my feelings.
I simply don't believe he has
the information you want.
Possibly.
Colonel Lovok will find out.
No.
I brought Odo here.
He's my prisoner
and my responsibility.
You don't have to do this.
Yes, I do.
And I think we both know
that you won't trust me
until I do.
All right.
I look forward
to hearing your results.
( console beeping )
Commander,
I'm reading some kind
of power fluctuation
in the cloaking device.
What kind of fluctuation?
I don't know.
I can't locate the source
of the problem,
but it is
getting worse.
KIRA:
We're de-cloaking.
All stop. Full scan,
Lieutenant.
Are there any other
ships in the area?
No, nothing in
sensor range.
Commander,
if the Jem'Hadar show up
while we're de-cloaked...
We'll have to fight
our way out of here.
Everything looks fine.
The power converters
are on line.
The projection matrix
looks normal.
The cloaking device
should be working.
Maybe there's some kind
of spatial anomaly nearby
that's interfering
with the cloak's
power systems.
This isn't the result
of a spatial anomaly, Major.
The tetryon compositor
on the cloaking device
has been sabotaged.
How do you know that?
Because I sabotaged it.
Why?
I was under orders
from Admiral Toddman
to stop you from pursuing
the Romulan/Cardassian fleet.
O'BRIEN:
You've turned us
into sitting ducks
for the Jem'Hadar!
But we can still
defend ourselves.
I didn't damage any
of the ship's weapon systems
or the engines.
But, without the cloak,
we'll have to return to DS9.
I'm sorry, Commander.
I didn't want to do this.
Odo's my friend, too,
but I report directly
to Admiral Toddman
and he gave me
an explicit order.
I couldn't disobey it.
I don't suppose
you could.
Chief...
now that we know
that the problem
is in the tetryon
compositor,
how long until
you can fix it?
About ten hours.
You've got two.
On your way.
I'm afraid I'm going
to have to confine you
to quarters,
Mr. Eddington.
Sir, if we run
into the Jem'Hadar,
you're still going to need
a Chief Security Officer.
What makes you think
we'll trust you again?
Because I give you my word.
I make it a policy to
never question the word
of anyone who wears
that uniform.
Don't make me
change that policy.
Man your station, Commander.
But... I'd stay out
of the Chief's way
if I were you.
I realize it must be
nearly time for you
to return
to your liquid state,
so I thought I'd bring you
something to relax in.
How kind.
But before you
go for a swim,
I have a few questions
I'd like to ask you.
I have nothing to say.
Well, I had hoped
a few hours alone
might jog your memory,
but I can see
I'm going to have to take
some steps I'd hoped to avoid.
Oh, no, you're going to
torture me, aren't you?
How I've been
dreading this.
Please, have mercy, Garak.
You do have a certain
flair for sarcasm.
It's one of the things
I like about you.
You can go now.
I'd bring those guards
back, if I were you.
I'm not in a
very good mood.
Yes, under normal
circumstances,
you would pose quite
a threat to me.
You could turn yourself into,
uh, a Vicarian razorback
or stretch out your arms
and strangle me from
across the room.
But not this time.
Oh, and why is that?
Because this device is emitting
a quantum stasis field
designed to prevent
any changeling
from altering
his biomolecular structure.
( grunts )
Yes.
It must be
very disconcerting for you
to be locked into a humanoid
form, especially now.
I'm sure you were
looking forward
to returning
to your liquid state.
Tell me...
what will happen if you
can't revert to a liquid?
I don't know.
An honest answer.
But it's probably safe to say
that it won't be pleasant.
Garak, this is pointless.
There's nothing I can tell you
about the Founders
that you don't already know.
I wish I could believe that.
Then why don't you?
Because you and I are so alike.
We both value our privacy,
our secrets.
That's why I know there's
something about the Founders
you haven't told anyone.
Something you didn't even share
with Starfleet
and Commander Sisko, hmm?
But you are going
to tell me, Odo.
There's nothing to tell!
Well, perhaps something
will come to you.
I can wait.
The question is...
can you?
Major...
leave the Chief alone.
What makes you think
I'm going to see O'Brien?
All right, it's
been three hours.
I just wanted to see
if he needed some help.
If he needed help,
he would ask for it.
For now, the best thing
we can do
is to stay out of his way.
( sighs )
( shuddering )
What's the matter, Garak?
You don't look very happy.
Aren't you enjoying yourself?
There is no pleasure
in this for me, Constable.
I assure you.
I am simply doing my job.
Your job?
Yes!
This job you've been
waiting for...
all... all these years of exile.
And here you are,
interrogating a prisoner again.
It must fill you with pride.
Odo, just tell me what I need
to know, and this will end.
( screaming )
But... but... but you don't
want it to end, do you, Garak?
Isn't this what you've
been dreaming of?
Back at work...
serving Cardassia.
That's right.
And you have information
that I need,
information that it's my duty
to extract from you.
It's not personal.
( screaming )
Odo, talk to me!
Tell me something!
Anything.
Lie if you have to,
but say it now, please.
Home! I want to go home!
And you will, I promise.
As soon as
this is all over,
I promise I'll take you back
to Deep Space 9.
No! Not the station.
Home with my people.
The Founders?
Yes.
You want to return
to the Founders?
Yes.
I thought you turned
your back on them.
I did, but they're
still my people.
I tried to deny it.
I tried to forget.
But I can't.
They're my people,
and I want to be with
them in the Great Link.
I knew there was
something secret
you were holding back.
And now you've found it.
I hope it's useful.
Repairs are
complete, sir.
The cloaking device
is on line.
A souvenir
of your handiwork.
Engage cloak.
DAX:
The cloak is
operating normally.
Resume course
to the Founders' planet.
Maximum warp.
Did you get anything
out of him at all?
Nothing.
He never broke.
Well, that's unfortunate.
I see no further use
for Mr. Odo.
Terminate him.
On the other hand, he is a
member of the Bajoran Militia
and an officer
on Deep Space 9.
We may not wish to provoke
the Federation by killing him.
I agree with Garak.
Do you?
Yes. There's no
way to be certain
that all of the
Founders will be
on the planet
when we attack.
We should be prepared
to encounter
other changelings
in the future.
And we could use
more information
on their capabilities.
I want to take Odo back to
Romulus for further study.
All right, in the interest
of cooperation.
ROMULAN:
Bridge to Colonel Lovok.
This is Lovok.
We have entered
the Omarion Nebula
and dropped out of warp.
We should be in orbit of
the planet in 15 minutes.
Acknowledged.
Well, it seems the moment
is nearly at hand.
Gentlemen.
Can I do something
for you, Colonel?
Why were you trying to
protect the changeling?
I wasn't trying
to protect him.
And as I recall, you thought
it was a good idea
to keep him alive as well.
My interest in
the changeling
is based on
what I believe to be
the strategic interests
of the Romulan Empire.
But you... you seem to have
a personal interest in him.
Well, tell me,
what else am I feeling?
I've never been
psychoanalyzed
by a Romulan before.
This is a fascinating
experience.
You are a practiced
liar, Mr. Garak,
but I am a
practiced observer.
And I can assure you,
I am going to be
observing you
very closely.
HELM:
We are within disruptor range.
Scan the planet for life-signs.
Sensors show multiple
life-forms on the surface.
They appear to be
in a liquid state.
The Founders.
Signal the fleet
to charge weapons
and lock on to
their targets.
We will open fire
the moment we drop
our cloaks.
All ships report ready,
all weapons charged.
So much for the Dominion.
Open fire.
HELM:
The first barrage
is complete.
Effect?
30 percent
of the planetary crust
destroyed on opening volley.
No change in life-form readings.
What?
That's impossible.
Some of them had
to be killed.
Our sensor readings
have been confirmed
by three other warbirds.
There's no change
in the number of life-signs
on the surface.
They're using
an automated transponder
to send back
false sensor readings.
The planet's deserted!
Colonel, signal the fleet...
Colonel, there are
ships coming out
of the nebula.
What type of ships?
Jem'Hadar fighters.
How many?
I asked you a question!
One hundred fifty.
Tactical display on screen.
GARAK:
It's a trap.
They've been waiting
for us all along.
( alarm blaring )
The Cardassian Cruiser
Koranak has been destroyed.
Romulan Warbirds Makar
and Belak have lost
main power.
Bring us about
to 318 mark 215.
Concentrate fire
on ships attacking
on the port quarter.
( yells )
The Jem'Hadar will destroy
every ship if we stay!
Our only hope is to return
to the Alpha Quadrant!
There's no way
out of here, Garak.
The Jem'Hadar have cut us off.
We need to consolidate the fleet
and make our stand here.
How could this be?
What could have happened?
I'm afraid the fault, dear Tain,
is not in our stars
but in ourselves.
What?!
Something I learned
from Dr. Bashir.
Main power's out.
Switching to emergency backups.
Bridge to Engineering.
We need power to the weapons.
Bridge to Engineering,
respond!
I'll be in Engineering.
Tain, take command
of the Bridge.
Four more Jem'Hadar vessels
closing on our position.
( grunts )
I take it the attack
on the Founders
is not proceeding
according to plan.
No, it's not, but I suggest
we make our way to the runabout.
For once, Garak,
I agree with you.
You'll need this in order to
gain access to your runabout.
Why are you doing this?
Because no changeling
has ever harmed another.
You are one
of the Founders?
Of course.
This whole plan
was the Founders' idea
in the first place.
You wanted
the Tal Shiar
and the Obsidian Order
to combine forces
and come into
the Gamma Quadrant
so you could
wipe them out.
Not exactly--
Tain originated the plan,
and when we learned of it,
we did everything we could
to carry it forward.
The Tal Shiar
and the Obsidian Order
are both ruthless,
efficient organizations.
A definite
threat to us.
But not after today.
After today,
the only real threat to us
from the Alpha Quadrant
are the Klingons
and the Federation.
And I doubt that
either of them
will be a threat
for much longer.
It is not too late
for you, Odo.
Come with me.
You can still become one
with the Great Link,
if you wish.
Thank you.
But my answer
is still no.
Come on! I don't think
we have much time.
The runabout is that way.
Two decks down, section 25.
Wait for me there.
Where are you going?
To the Bridge,
to get Tain.
What?
I know it's difficult for you
to understand, Constable,
but I still owe him
a personal debt
and I have to try
to repay it.
Wait for us
as long as you can.
GARAK:
Tain! We have to go!
There must have been
an informant.
That's the only
explanation.
Yes, there was an informant.
You're right.
Colonel Lovok
is a changeling.
Lovok?
Yes, but that's something
we can discuss at another time.
Right now, we have to...
It appears I have
underestimated the Founders.
I should have seen it coming.
There was a time
when nothing got past me.
You remember, don't you, Elim?
Yes, I do!
But now we have to go!
Go where? Back to Mila
and my quiet retirement?
I don't think so.
I must be getting old.
I let my pride
override my instinct.
Wouldn't have played it
that way in the old days.
In the old days, I would have
kept Lovok at arm's length.
He was too cagey, too smart.
I can't just leave you here!
I always did have
a soft spot for you, Garak.
Another of my flaws.
Enabran!
( grunts )
These Founders, Elim,
they're very good.
Next time, we should
be more careful.
You can be very persuasive
on occasion, Constable.
But in the future,
I hope you'll consider
using gentler language.
I'll keep that in mind.
A Jem'Hadar ship
is following us.
Raise shields and
charge the weapons.
Aft shields
down to 50 percent.
More speed would
be advisable.
The warp drive
is off-line.
Shields down
to 30 percent!
Another Jem'Hadar ship is
approaching to starboard.
Hang on!
Shields down
to 15 percent.
Main power is failing.
We're losing speed.
The shields are gone.
Odo, I hope
that you will accept
my sincere apologies
for all this.
A little late, isn't it?
Nevertheless.
I may not agree
with what you did,
but I can certainly understand
your desire to return home.
Thank you.
( console beeping )
What?
Three more coming in
off the port bow.
Fire on the lead ship, then
bring us back to the runabout.
Two life-signs on
the runabout, Commander.
Drop shields.
Bridge to Transporter Room.
Beam them aboard, Chief.
O'BRIEN: Aye, sir.
Four more Jem'Hadar ships
closing to starboard.
O'Brien to Bridge.
I've got them.
Raise shields.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
Oh, that
looks painful.
It is,
but it did save my life.
Shields at 80 percent.
Attack pattern Omega four.
Full impulse power.
Hold your fire until we're
within 500 meters.
We might get pretty singed
at that range.
Not as singed
as they're going to get.
Engage!
50,000 meters and closing.
2,000 meters.
Five hundred.
Fire!
The third Jem'Hadar ship
is still pursuing.
Aft torpedoes, fire!
KIRA:
Direct hit on
their port nacelle.
They're losing speed.
We're out
of their weapons range.
Any other signs of pursuit?
DAX: Negative.
The other fighters
are still concentrating
on the remaining Romulan
and Cardassian ships.
Let's not wait around for them
to change their minds.
Set course for the wormhole,
Lieutenant, warp eight.
It's good to see
you again, Constable.
Likewise, Major.
DAX:
Course laid in.
Engage.
There is still
no indication
that any Romulan or
Cardassian vessel
survived the attack.
Sounds like Wolf 359
all over again.
I had the same thought.
You may be interested to know
I've decided not to file charges
against anyone
aboard the Defiant.
Thank you, sir.
But if you pull a stunt
like that again,
I'll court-martial you,
or I'll promote you.
Either way, you'll be
in a lot of trouble.
I'll keep that in mind, sir.
( sighs )
ODO:
I just read the report
that you wrote
and I wanted
to thank you.
Me? For what?
For not mentioning
my desire to return
to my people.
I consider
the entire conversation
as something...
best forgotten.
As do I.
Quark has expressed
an interest
in renting this space
if you're not going
to be using it.
Oh?
He mentioned something
about an Argelian
massage facility.
Unfortunately, I don't think
Commander Sisko would approve
of such an interesting facility
on the Promenade.
I tend to agree.
But I do think he would
approve of a tailor's shop.
Do you know
what the sad part is, Odo?
I'm a very good tailor.
Garak...
I was thinking
that you and I
should have breakfast
together sometime.
Why, Constable--
I thought
you didn't eat.
I don't.