( buzz of conversation )
Excuse me.
You're Dr. Bashir,
aren't you?
That's right.
I'm Leeta.
I've been meaning to come
by the Infirmary to see you.
( coughs )
Oh, dear.
How long have
you had that cough?
A few days now.
May I?
Cough for me.
( coughs )
Hmm...
Is it serious,
Doctor?
No, but it's
a good thing
you came to me
when you did.
We need to start your
treatment immediately.
Bring me
a Fanalian toddy
very hot.
Make that two.
I'm feeling a bit of a cough
coming on, myself.
I'm... sorry to
hear that, Doctor.
No, please.
Call me...
Julian.
Hi.
I'm Jadzia.
Leeta.
Before I forget...
here's that immunological
data you asked for.
How nice of you
to put it together
for me so quickly.
I, uh... I think I'll
go over it right now.
Oh, by the way
I hear the Lexington
is docking here
for a few days.
The Lexington?
Excuse me, um...
for just one second.
Stay there.
Jadzia!
Do you happen to know when
the Lexington is coming in?
Three weeks.
Don't you have a friend aboard?
Do I?
The Medical Officer--
Elizabeth Lense.
Elizabeth Lense...
You know, I think
she may have been
in my class
at Starfleet Medical.
Wasn't she valedictorian?
That's right.
And you were
salutatorian.
Second in my class.
But if I hadn't mistaken
that preganglionic fiber...
For a postganglionic nerve--
um, I know.
I would have been valedictorian.
You must be looking forward
to seeing her.
I can hardly wait.
Hey, Jake-o.
Hey, Dad.
Hey!
What is this?
I thought it was
time for a change.
What do you think?
I like it.
Yeah.
How was Bajor?
Beautiful! You should
have come with me.
The reopening
of some old library
isn't exactly my idea
of a good time.
This wasn't just
some old library.
We're talking about the
most extensive collection
of Bajoran antiquities
on the planet.
I saw manuscripts
that dated back
to before the fall
of the First Republic.
Great.
Here...
look at this.
What is this,
some kind of ship?
According to legend,
the ancient Bajorans
used ships like these
to explore their star system
800 years ago.
You mean
that when humans
were first sailing
across the oceans,
Bajorans were already
going to other planets?
Some scholars say
they made it all
the way to Cardassia.
Ah, that seems hard
to believe.
What are these?
Solar sails.
These ships were propelled
by light pressure.
Like a sailboat
catching the wind.
Exactly.
I wonder if a ship like that
could really fly.
I don't know.
That's why I'm going
to build one.
I'm expecting
a lumber shipment
from Bajor
this afternoon.
Okay.
Which reminds me--
I'll need a saber saw.
A saber saw?
You know, to cut wood.
Why not use
a laser cutter?
Oh, no, I
want to use
the same types of tools
the Bajorans had.
This will do fine, Major.
As soon as these cargo
containers are out of the way,
I'll start construction.
Sir, I've looked over
the specifications
you brought back
from Bajor.
I'm not sure this design
is spaceworthy,
and I'm positive
a ship like this
could never have made it
from Bajor to Cardassia.
Now, why would
you say that?
At sublight speeds,
the trip would
have taken them years,
and that's assuming
ideal conditions.
One unexpected
ion storm
in the Denorios Belt
would have torn
the sails to pieces
and left them stranded.
Well, maybe
they were lucky
and they didn't
go into any storms.
O'BRIEN:
I just don't see
how this ship could
have made the trip.
They didn't even have
replicators back then.
They would have had
to store their air supply.
And there's only room
on board
for a few weeks' worth.
Well, maybe they
recycled it somehow--
used some kind of
photosynthetic plant.
Yeah, maybe.
Oh, you sound just
like a Cardassian.
I beg your pardon?
They have denied
the possibility
of ancient contact
for decades,
because they cannot
stand the idea
of Bajor having
interstellar flight
before they did.
With all due respect, Major,
you're beginning to sound
like a Romulan.
A Romulan!
O'BRIEN:
There is no piece
of technology in existence
they don't claim
they invented
before everyone else.
Look, I don't plan to spend
the next few years
sailing to Cardassia.
All I want is to build
one of these ships
and prove
that it's spaceworthy.
A computer model
could do that.
Why go to all
that trouble?
Why?
Because it'll be fun.
( sighs )
( grunts )
Oh, yes.
You know, I've been thinking.
According to the star charts,
the most difficult part
of the trip
between Bajor and Cardassia
would be getting through
the Denorios Belt.
After that, it would be smooth
sailing the rest of the way.
Really?
Just making that part
of the trip would go
a long way towards demonstrating
that the Bajorans
could have made
the journey to Cardassia.
Seems reasonable.
It should only take
about four, five days.
That's not so long.
So?
What?
So, what do you say
you come with me?
We'll have a great time.
The ship will be ready to go
in another week.
That's when Leanne is supposed
to be getting back from Bajor.
I really want to see her,
and I don't know
how long she's going to be here.
Oh, well...
if you can't do it...
you can't do it.
I'd like to, but...
it's just not good timing,
you know.
Sure.
I understand.
( sparks crackling )
Hi!
Oh, hello, Jadzia.
I brought you
something to eat.
Oh, thank you.
Let me just finish
this welding,
and I'll take a break.
Benjamin, I
can't believe
the work you've
put into this.
I'm just following
the blueprint.
But you didn't
have to bother
with detail like this
to prove that the
ship is spaceworthy.
Oh, I suppose not,
but I want everything
to be just right.
It's an exact replica,
you know
except for the gravity net
that I installed in the floor.
Weightlessness
makes me queasy.
( laughs )
Ooh, I haven't seen you
like this for a long time.
Like what?
So caught up
in something.
So excited.
Not since, um...
not since you and Jennifer
decided to have a baby.
Ah, the nursery.
I don't think anyone's
ever put such effort
into making a room
for their child.
Well, you have to admit,
it turned out pretty well.
Oh...
especially the starscape
on the ceiling.
Yeah, Jake loved that ceiling.
In fact, when we
moved out of the house,
he couldn't understand why
we couldn't bring it with us.
You're disappointed
he's not going with you
on this trip, aren't you?
Well, he has other things
he'd rather be doing.
Friends he'd rather be with.
It's funny...
a year or two ago, nothing
would have stopped him
from coming with me
on an adventure like this.
I guess I waited too long.
You'll have other adventures,
Benjamin.
They'll just be different.
Believe me, I know.
I've been a father
a couple of
times myself.
Oh, I could tell you stories.
You already have.
That's right, I have, haven't I?
Then you know I'm right.
Computer...
are there any messages for me?
COMPUTER: One.
A communication
from Wellington, New Zealand.
Display it on screen.
( sighs )
Hello.
Welcome aboard, son.
Hey, Dad.
So...
what do you think?
Well, it's wonderful.
Maybe a bit small for
two people, but, uh...
I think I could
get used to it.
That is, uh, if you
still want me along.
( chuckles )
Oh...
"A Survey of Cygnian
Respiratory Diseases"?
Fascinating.
Yeah, I'm reading
just about everything
I can get my hands on.
I don't want to be
caught flat-footed
by our intrepid
Dr. Lense.
It's useless,
of course.
She's probably discovered
the cure to aging by now.
I take it the two of you
are competitive?
Absolutely.
We were neck and neck
right until the final exam.
Then... I blew it.
That's how she wound up
on the Lexington--
a post which virtually everyone
in our graduating class
was hoping for.
Including you?
No, this is the assignment
I wanted.
Then what does it matter?
Well, don't
you see?
She could have had this post.
She could have taken it from me.
No matter what I accomplish
while I'm here,
somehow, that'll always
make me feel...
second best.
I understand you're
planning a trip.
Word gets around.
I can't believe
that a man of your intelligence
would take stock
in Bajoran fairy tales
about ancient contact.
If you recall,
you thought the Celestial Temple
was a Bajoran fairy tale
until we discovered
the wormhole.
I suggest you
reconsider your plans.
Solar vessels are very fragile,
and it's a long way
to the Denorios Belt
at sublight speeds.
Don't worry.
I'll have emergency equipment
on board.
If something goes wrong,
Major Kira can have a runabout
to me within an hour.
An hour can be a very long time
especially if you happen to
encounter something unexpected.
Like what?
Oh, I don't know.
A Maquis ship, perhaps.
Why would the Maquis
have any quarrel
with an unarmed ship sailing
toward the Denorios Belt?
They have nothing at stake here,
nothing to prove--
or should I say, disprove.
Commander, I contacted you
out of concern for your safety,
but you seem to be intimating
that I've made
some sort of threat.
Ah, then I'm glad I was wrong.
For a moment there, I thought
that you had been put in charge
of the Cardassian Ministry
for the Refutation
of Bajoran Fairy Tales.
Since I don't seem
to be able to dissuade you
from undertaking
this little voyage of yours,
I'll wish you luck instead.
Let's hope you don't need it.
All right, first, we have
to deploy the mainsails.
I want you to take
that winch right there.
Huh? Release brakes.
All right.
When I give
you the word,
crank it with
all you got.
And... now.
That's as far
as they'll go.
Lock it off.
All right...
let's work on
the spritsails.
Psst.
Oh.
All right, now get
your back into it, huh?
All right.
That's right.
We'll make a sailor
out of you yet.
These will trim
the spritsails.
Now I get it.
What?
Why you wanted
to build this ship.
It is beautiful,
isn't it?
Jake-o.
Trim the starboard sprit
about six degrees.
Okay.
How's that?
That should do it.
We'll start
to pick up speed
as the pressure
on the sails builds.
Hey, Dad...
where do
we sleep?
We have hammocks
we can string up later.
Is this the bathroom?
Yes, it was designed
for a zero-gravity
environment.
Well, how am I supposed to...?
How are you supposed to, um...?
You'll get the hang of it.
Hmm.
We'll be tacking
against the light
most of the way.
And then we'll run like this
for about 90 minutes or so
and come about.
And I'll calculate
the next leg
of our trip.
How about something
to drink?
Yeah, sure.
Don't tell me we only have
zero-gravity rations.
It's all
the ancient Bajorans had.
( sighs )
Listen.
I don't hear anything.
Exactly.
Not even the hum of an engine.
It's almost like being on
the deck of an old sailing ship.
Except the stars
are not just up in the sky,
they're all around us.
Imagine how the ancient Bajorans
must have felt
heading into space
in a ship like this one,
not knowing what they
were going to find
or who they were
going to meet.
Jake...
I know that you really didn't
want to come on this trip.
I just want to say,
I'm glad you're here.
Dad, there's something
I need to talk to you about.
What is it?
First, you should read this.
It's a story
I wrote.
Ah, a story.
That's why you kept
putting this away
every time I walked
into the room, huh?
Well, if you'll keep an eye
on the rigging,
I'll read it right now.
Deal.
ODO:
It looked better
where it was before.
I thought you might want to know
the Lexington docked
a few minutes ago.
Already?
Oh, I thought it wasn't coming
for another day or two.
She's in Quark's.
( whispers ):
Oh, okay.
Are you going to
talk to her or not?
She's busy.
You never mentioned
she was beautiful.
I never mentioned
her at all,
not to you, anyway.
Morn gave me three-to-one odds
that you'll exchange
awkward pleasantries
for a few minutes,
then say good-bye.
I'm betting that your charm
will take you further.
( snickers )
Okay then.
In the ship?
She's getting up.
See you there.
All right.
So, what do you think?
I liked it.
You're not just saying that?
No, no, no.
It's good.
What do you think
about the part
where Jared thinks
he's been betrayed?
I don't think that he would
confront him with it.
Not right away.
Yeah, I guess
he could wait
until he gets back from
the Demilitarized Zone.
Yeah, that'd make it
more believable.
Hmm.
So, you really think
it was good, huh?
I think it shows
a lot of promise.
What?
Promise?
In a few places,
you're writing about things
you haven't
actually experienced,
or at least I hope
you haven't experienced.
Unless you've joined the Maquis
without telling me.
I can't talk about it.
( laughing ):
I had you going there.
Jake, I really am impressed.
I think you should
keep writing.
I'm thinking
about it.
Don't think about it,
just do it.
What I... what I mean is...
Yesterday, I got a communication
from the Pennington School
in New Zealand,
and, uh...
they offered me
a writing fellowship.
Oh, well, Jake, that...
that's terrific.
I, uh...
I didn't realize
you had applied.
Well I-I
didn't, really.
What happened is, I
showed a story I wrote
to Mrs. O'Brien.
I guess she liked it,
because she showed it
to a friend of hers who knows
someone at the school, and...
( rumbling )
A mast support gave way.
The starboard sprit
is fouling one of the mainsails.
Can we fix it?
I don't think so.
We're going to have
to jettison the sprit.
Let's fall off a little.
Take some pressure
off the sails.
Lock that down
and give me a hand.
One more turn.
Lock it!
Good work.
I'm going to
jettison the sprit.
That's better,
but we're still getting
a lot of spill off the sails.
We won't be able to make
much headway with each tack.
I don't think we'll be able
to get to the Denorios Belt
like this.
The ancient Bajorans
probably ran into
these kinds of problems.
I suppose they did.
Well, did they give up
and go home?
It seems to me, we're here
to prove that they didn't.
What are we waiting for?
Let's get to work.
Lay out the port sprit.
Coming about.
O'BRIEN AND BASHIR:
♪ Bring me my chariots ♪
♪ Of fire ♪
♪ I will not cease ♪
♪ From mental fight ♪
♪ Nor shall my sword ♪
♪ Sleep in my hand ♪
♪ Till we have built ♪
♪ Jerusalem ♪
♪ In England's green ♪
♪ And pleasant land. ♪
Ha!
That was really
beautiful, Chief.
You know what
we should do?
What?
We should go to Quark's
and sing it for everybody.
Oh, no. I-I-I think
we should switch to synthale.
No, no, this isn't...
a synthale kind of night.
( sighs )
She walked right
past me, Chief.
Acted like I
wasn't even there.
Do you know what I think?
What?
I think she's
in love with you.
I don't think so.
It's the only explanation.
Unless...
( laughs )
( snorts )
Unless she really
ignored you
because she can't
stand you.
( laughs )
Isn't there some
explanation in between?
Well...
you're not
an in-between kind of guy.
What do you mean?
Well, people either
love you or hate you.
Really?
I mean, I hated you
when we first met.
I remember.
But now...
And now?
Well... now I don't.
( sighs )
That means a lot to me, Chief.
It really does.
Really!
Now...
that is from
the heart, huh?
Huh? I really do.
Not hate you
anymore.
Hey, do you know
what I think?
What?
If you want to know
why she ignored you,
you have got
to confront her.
You're right.
I got to go
right up to her...
and ask her flat out
where she gets off
walking past me like that.
Better wait until tomorrow.
Why?
Why not right now?
Because you can barely
stand up right now.
Good point.
( exhales )
BOTH:
♪ And did those feet ♪
♪ In ancient time ♪
♪ Walk upon England's
mountains... ♪
Lock it.
Coming about.
Now.
Good.
Solid job.
Let's take a break.
String up the hammock.
Hammock time.
Yo!
Hop in.
Phew!
Oh!
Nice.
Whoa!
I'm okay.
Comfortable,
isn't it?
I'm fine. Yeah.
Yeah, we'll make
a sailor of you yet.
I suppose
congratulations
are in order.
Pennington is
a good school--
and very competitive.
Dad, before you say anything,
I'm turning down the fellowship.
Turning it down?
Why?
I'm just... not ready to go.
Jake, an opportunity
like this
doesn't come
along every day.
I can defer admission
for a year.
If I want to go then,
I still can.
Well, that's fine,
but why will things be
different in a year?
I don't know.
They just might be, that's all.
Now, remember, Jake.
I wasn't much older than you
when I left for San Francisco
to go to Starfleet Academy.
For the first
few days,
I was so homesick,
that I'd go back
to my house in New Orleans
every night for dinner.
I'd materialize
in my living room
at 6:30 every night
and take my seat at the table,
just like I had come downstairs.
You must have used up
a month's worth
of transporter credits.
Hmm.
My parents, they never said
anything about it.
Just "How you doing, son?
How was school today?"
They knew that I would get over
being homesick soon enough.
Well, after about the
fifth, sixth day,
you couldn't pry me
from that campus.
Of course now, if you go
to Pennington,
you won't be able to beam
back to the station
to have dinner
with your old man.
After about a week or so,
you'll get over it.
It's not me
I'm worried about.
It's you.
Me?
Well, if I go,
you'll be all alone.
Well, I appreciate
you thinking about me, Jake,
but please don't turn down
this opportunity on my account.
I'll have plenty of people
to keep me company.
I can always eat dinner
with Dax or Dr. Bashir
or... even Quark.
I guess.
I'd feel a lot better
if you had someone.
You know, someone special,
like a girlfriend.
I see.
Well, let's
face it.
It's been over a year
since your last date.
A year, Dad.
Well, you got to make time
for these things.
I cannot believe
that I'm getting advice
about women from my son.
Don't think of me
as your son right now.
Just think of me as another guy.
( laughs )
Another guy who happens to know
a very attractive lady
who wants to meet you.
( chuckles )
You are trying to set me up?
Why not?
( both laughing )
( crashing )
What was that?
I'm not sure,
but whatever hit us
almost tore off
the port mainsail.
Main power is off-line.
We're moving at warp.
How can that be?
I don't know.
What happened?
That's a good question.
There's no record
of any spatial anomalies
in this region.
What are these?
Tachyon eddies.
They run all
through this area.
Could we have gotten
caught up in one?
No, tachyons don't
have enough mass
to affect a ship of...
This... isn't
an ordinary ship.
It has a lot more
surface area
relative to
its mass.
Because of the sails.
And since tachyons
travel faster than light,
it could be that their impact
on the sails
somehow accelerated us
to warp speeds.
We could be light-years
off course.
The question is...
where did we end up?
You check the rigging.
I'll try to
figure that out.
We lost the jib
and port mainsail.
Damn!
What?
It's useless.
Now we can't figure out
where we are
or where we're going.
Guess we'll have to contact
the station.
Let them know they have
to come and get us.
We were so close.
Another day and we
would have made it
to the Denorios Belt.
Hey, we did pretty well
getting as far as we did.
Is something wrong?
The station's
not responding.
Is the com unit
damaged?
Not as far as I can see.
Maybe they haven't
received our message yet.
Do you think we could have
been carried that far away
from the
station?
I suppose it's possible.
Well... they'll
find us eventually.
Right?
Sure.
Excuse me.
Yes?
We were at medical
school together.
Julian Bashir.
You're Bashir?
You sound surprised.
Well, I thought
you were Andorian.
Andorian?
Someone
pointed out
an Andorian to me at a party
and said
that that was Julian Bashir.
It was, um, New Year's Eve
at Bruce Lucier's
four years ago.
Well, I did go to that party.
May I?
Yes.
With my friend, Erib.
Now, he's Andorian.
No, thank you.
I must have gotten
you mixed up.
All these years, I thought
you were someone else.
Didn't you see me give
my speech at graduation?
No, I was back stage,
waiting to give my speech.
I was so nervous,
I almost passed out.
I know the feeling.
So, you gave me
quite a run for my money.
If it hadn't been
for that preganglionic fiber...
You know about that.
I know that if you
hadn't got that wrong,
you would be valedictorian.
Well, I never got a chance
to congratulate you.
It seems like
a long time ago, doesn't it?
Not so long.
So, you got the Lexington.
You must have had
quite an adventure
exploring uncharted space
meeting fascinating
new species
with fascinating
new diseases.
Actually, it ended up being
more of a charting expedition.
Sometimes it would be months
between planetary systems.
You wouldn't believe
how excited I would get
if we actually found
something living,
even if it was just moss
under a rock.
Don't take this the wrong way,
but... there were times
when I regretted
not taking your assignment.
Really?
I read your paper on the
immunotherapy project
you've been doing on Bajor.
It was brilliant.
Thank you.
I really
envy
the opportunity you have
to work on that kind
of long-term project.
On the Lexington,
it was collect
your samples
and then on to
the next system.
I suppose I was lucky...
What's happening
on Bajor?
Were you able to get the T cell
anomalies under control?
If you're
really that interested,
we should go to the Infirmary,
and I can show you
my latest results.
I'd love it.
Morn, about that bet.
I believe the odds
were three to one.
So, Dad...
we're not going
to run out of air
or anything, are we?
Don't worry.
Somebody will find us
before that happens.
Hmm.
So...
tell me about this woman
you want me to meet.
Well...
she's a freighter Captain.
( whistles )
A freighter Captain.
Well, Dad, trust me.
You'll like her.
All right.
I'll agree to meet her,
on one condition.
What?
That you agree not
to base your decision
about going to Pennington
on how our date turns out.
Don't worry.
I won't.
I've already decided
to wait at least a year.
Why?
Well...
I've heard
that you can only write
about what you've experienced.
And you-you got to admit,
Deep Space 9 is a pretty
good place to get experience.
Dad.
It appears we've
got company.
What do you think
they want?
( com beeping )
Hmm. Looks like we're
about to find out.
SISKO:
What can I do
for you, Dukat?
Well, I wanted to be the
first one to congratulate you.
Congratulate me?
On managing to make it
all the way here.
All the way where?
Don't you know?
You've just entered
the Cardassian system.
The tachyon eddy.
It must have taken us
past the Denorios Belt
and brought us here.
The same thing
must have happened
to the ancient Bajorans.
We did it!
We proved the trip
was possible.
DUKAT: I hate to interrupt
your celebration, Commander,
but I've been asked
to convey a message
from the Cardassian government.
"Your voyage is a testament
"to the spirit
of the ancient Bajorans
"who first ventured
out into space.
"It could not be
more appropriate
"that your arrival coincides
"with the discovery
here on Cardassia
"of an ancient crash site--
"a site that our
archaeologists believe
"contains the remnants
of one of the Bajoran vessels
whose journey
you have just recreated."
What an amazing
coincidence.
Yes, isn't it?
Welcome.
( distant explosions )