( Sisko humming )
( food sizzling )
Hey, Dad.
Jake-o.
Take your seat.
Dinner's almost ready.
Hmm. Let me guess.
You've convinced
the Peljenites
to exchange Ambassadors
with the Federation.
How did you know
that? Ah!
You're cooking
chicken paprikish.
Paprikash.
You only cook
Hungarian food
when you're in
a really good mood.
You know, I always said
that you are a smart child.
Runs in
the family.
Huh.
You know, I have
some good news, too.
Captain Yates is
back on the station.
Huh.
Kasidy Yates.
Who?
The freighter captain
I told you about.
The one you want me
to meet.
I could, uh,
invite her over for dinner.
How about tomorrow night?
Jake, I think we're getting a
little ahead of ourselves here.
I know you want me to meet her,
and I will.
Just let me handle it my way.
You're going
to like her, Dad.
You never know.
The place is packed.
Where's Nog?
I gave him
the night off.
You what?
He's studying for
his Starfleet exams.
He's a very
dedicated student.
He's a disgrace
to this family
and to Ferengi
everywhere.
He should be here,
helping us earn profit,
not in his room learning
how to be more like a human.
He doesn't want to
be human, Brother.
He just wants to
join Starfleet.
It's the same thing.
Don't you see?
That's how it begins.
All it takes is for
one impressionable youngster
to join Starfleet,
and the next thing you know,
a whole generation
of Ferengi
will be quoting
the Prime Directive
and abandoning
the pursuit of latinum.
It's the end of Ferengi
civilization as we know it.
And it's all your fault.
Relax, Brother.
Nog isn't going
to destroy
the Ferengi way of life.
He just wants a job
with better hours.
( chuckles )
( chuckles
patronizingly )
You must be Quark.
That's me.
What can I
do for you?
Brunt, FCA.
The Ferengi
Commerce Authority.
A Writ of
Accountability.
We're in trouble.
All right, everyone.
The bar is closed.
Everybody out.
Go, go, go.
Now, everybody.
This way.
Everybody out!
Out.
So, how do
you get to be
an FCA Liquidator,
anyway?
( thud )
( yelps )
Hard work, bribes
sucking up
to the boss--
just like
any other job.
Are these all
your assets?
Yes.
No.
( thud )
( yelps )
Down to the last slip
of latinum.
You realize concealing
financial information
from the FCA
could result
in severe fines.
I would never
dream of trying
to hide anything
from the FCA.
We'll see.
Uh, can I look over
those figures again?
Yes.
Wait a minute.
That can't be right.
Rom, you forgot
to include the
profit figures
for the tulaberry
wine franchise.
But you told me...
( thud )
( gasps )
Go get them now.
Yes, Brother.
You'll have to excuse Rom.
He means well, but he can be
a lobeless idiot sometimes.
Hmm.
Please, provide a dermal imprint
for FCA records.
But you haven't even told me
what I'm being charged with.
No, I haven't.
Oh!
How rude of me.
For your troubles.
You're being charged
with violating
Ferengi Trade Bylaw
Subsection 1,027,
Paragraph Three.
Paragraph Three?
I'm not sure I'm
familiar with that one.
Well, in that case, you
need a copy of the Bylaws.
Which you just happen to have.
Subsection 1,027...
Paragraph Three.
"Improper supervision
of a family member."
You are being held accountable
for the criminal activities
of one Ishka
daughter of Adred,
wife of Keldar.
Ishka-- you mean
our mother.
What's she done?
She's charged
with... earning profit.
Earning profit?
Our Moogie?
Odo, I'm holding you
personally responsible
for the safety
of my bar
and my personal
possessions
for as long as I'm
off the station.
And make sure my
thieving brother
doesn't touch
anything.
Going somewhere?
Back to the
homeworld
to take care
of some business.
Little trouble
with the FCA?
How'd you know?
Huh.
I won't be gone long.
All I've got to do
is get my mother
to confess to her crimes,
and I'll be
on the next transport
back the station.
Your mother?
What's she done?
It doesn't matter.
The important thing is,
I'm required by law
to get her to admit
her wrongdoing,
make reparations,
and reveal her accomplices.
And that is
what I'm going to do.
Assuming she cooperates.
Well... she'd better.
I have no intention
of spending my latinum
to make restitution
for her crimes.
I will wring that confession
out of her, if I have to.
This is your mother
you're talking about?
Don't remind me.
Ah!
Ah-- Chief O'Brien
wants to know
when you can stop by
and inspect
the new runabout.
I'll be available
at 1400 hours.
Tell him that I want
to name it the Rubicon.
The Rubicon it is.
You know, the rate we
go through runabouts,
it's a good thing
the Earth has
so many rivers.
Hmm.
Have you met her yet?
Met who?
Captain Yates.
How did you know about her?
Jake introduced us.
So, are you going to
ask her out for dinner?
I'm considering it.
What did you think about her?
Let me just put it this way.
If I were Curzon,
I'd have stolen her
from you by now.
That's one of the reasons
I'm glad you're not
Curzon anymore.
( whispering )
Brother, wait!
I'm coming with you.
No, you're not.
Yes, I am.
What did I tell you
about contradicting me?
You told me
not to do it.
That's right, so you're
going to stay here
and watch over the
bar while I'm gone.
No, I'm not.
The bar is closed.
There's no reason
why I can't come along.
You want a reason?
I'll give you a reason.
I don't want you to.
And you know why?
Because you'll just
take her side.
You mean Moogie.
Yes, I mean Moogie.
Stop calling her by
that infantile nickname.
But she likes it.
Well, I don't.
Well, she does.
You see?
You always take her side.
Somebody has to.
After all, she is our mother.
Now, I'm coming with you,
and that's final.
All right!
Fine.
Come if you want.
Just remember
one thing:
This is between Moog...
Mother and me.
So if you know
what's good for you,
you'll stay out of the way.
( thunder rumbling )
( shuddering )
Welcome to our home.
Oh.
Um.
Please place your imprint
on the legal waivers
and deposit
your admission fee
in the box by the door.
Remember, my house
is my house.
As are its contents.
It's good to be back,
isn't it, Brother?
Now that you
mention it, no.
But you haven't been
here in 20 years.
If I had my way, I would
have been gone another 20.
Oh.
Hmm-- Mother certainly
has been acquiring
quite a few new things.
Uh, doubtless with the generous
stipend you give her.
Look, Brother.
The latinum tooth sharpener
I used when we were children.
All I had was
a cheap wooden
chew stick.
Excuse me
for interrupting,
but we do have business
to attend to.
As a registered Liquidator,
it's my duty to present
a formal list
of the infractions
committed by your mother.
You have three days
to obtain
an admission of guilt
from the accused.
Three days...
is that all?
If you're not able
to obtain
a confession, your mother
will be placed
in indentured servitude
and you will be required
to make restitution
for her crimes.
Do you understand
everything I've said to you?
FEMALE:
He understands,
all right.
Not that it matters.
I'm not confessing anything.
Moogie.
Oh, it's good
to see you, son.
You look well.
And you look...
dressed.
Oh! Now, now...
Your mother is wearing clothes.
Mother, get undressed
this instant.
Hello, Quark.
You haven't
changed a bit.
Perhaps I should leave.
Perhaps you should.
Wa... was she addressing me?
No, no, not at all.
ISHKA:
Of course I was.
This is my home, and I'll
speak to whomever I want.
But, Moogie, he's a stranger,
and you're female.
It's all right, Rom,
I know what I'm doing.
Perhaps you do,
but I will not stand here
and be spoken to by a female.
Wait, I'm sure there's
an explanation.
You have three days
to get your house
in order.
( disgusted groans )
Now, see what you've done.
Oh.
Quark, you're
upsetting your brother.
He's not
the only one
who's upset, not that
anyone cares how I feel.
That's not true.
I care.
Then imprint this
and take off those clothes.
I'm not doing
anything of the kind.
Yes, you are.
You're going to make
a full confession
so that I can go back to my bar
and pretend none of this
has ever happened.
You mean, we're leaving so soon?
Rom, this is your home.
You can stay
as long as you like.
Or leave whenever you like,
it's up to you.
Same old Moogie.
Yeah.
Are you sure this
is absolutely necessary?
Well, I
don't know
if I would call
it necessary.
Constable, there's
no telling
how long Quark
could be away.
All we want is
our dart board.
Well, can't you just replicate
another one?
We could.
But we're not going to.
That's our dart board,
and we want it back.
If Quark was going to run off,
the least he could do
is give us some warning
so we could retrieve
our property.
It's the principle
of the thing.
Hmm.
Well, getting it back might not
be as simple as you think.
This is one of Rom's
special security locks.
I've never seen anything
so convoluted.
SISKO:
Gentlemen...
is there a problem?
Ah, well, it seems that Quark
has locked some of Chief O'Brien
and Dr. Bashir's
personal property
inside the bar.
Ah, let me guess.
Your lucky dart board.
We never said it was
a "lucky" dart board.
We're just used to playing
on it, that's all.
A little defensive,
aren't they?
( scoffs )
Ah, well, it looks like
it's a tripartite
micro-sealing mechanism.
It's going to take
you a long time
to get through that one.
If you want any suggestions
I'll be in
Cargo Bay...
Four.
Huh? Seven.
Oh, uh...
well, I thought...
Thought what?
I thought you were going to...
talk to the freighter captain.
You know, uh,
Jake's friend?
Oh.
How do you two know about her?
BASHIR:
The Chief told me.
Exactly how many people has
Jake told about this woman?
Everyone.
Huh.
( buzzing )
Tube grubs,
extra juicy.
Just the way
you like them.
What are you doing?
Serving dinner.
That's
Mother's job.
She's not feeling well.
Not feeling well?
Wait a minute.
That's not bad.
We could say she's having
emotional problems.
We might even be able
to get the FCA
to drop the charges,
in light of her illness.
Actually, all she has
is a slight rash.
Her skin's still a little
sensitive to clothing.
That's hardly an excuse not
to serve her sons dinner.
Look at this.
She hasn't even softened
the grubs for us.
You know Moogie.
She never liked
chewing our food for us.
Not even when we were children.
Oh, she always had her own way
of doing things.
You remember
how the other children
used to tease us about her?
"Your mother won't chew
your food."
"Your mother
talks to strangers."
It's like she went
out of her way
to embarrass us...
not to mention Father.
Oh, I remember.
There were nights when
I would find him sitting
slumped in this chair.
He'd say to me,
"Quark, I don't know
what I'm going to do
about that female."
No wonder he never
earned much profit.
He was too busy
worrying about her.
I thought Father did
all right.
He could have
done a lot better
if she'd just
behaved herself,
showed him the
respect he deserved.
Well, she may have
dragged Father down,
but she's not doing
the same to me.
It's time someone
put her in her place.
Have anyone in mind
for the job?
Mmm...
Dank and musty.
I hand-picked them
from the cellar.
Mother, we need to talk.
Forget it, Quark.
I am not imprinting
the confession.
Why not?
Imprinting the confession
doesn't take away
from your achievement.
Just admit to what you did,
and tell the FCA the name
of any male who might
have helped you.
What exactly did she do,
Brother?
Never mind what she did.
Why don't
you tell him?
Or would you prefer I did?
All right.
She took a part of
the monthly stipend I send her
and invested it
in a Hupyrian beetle farm.
High-quality beetles.
The best.
ROM:
Really?
How much did you make, Moogie?
Three bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
ROM:
Three bars
of latinum?
Isn't the FCA
overreacting a little?
It doesn't matter
whether it's one slip
or a hundred thousand bars.
Females are not allowed
to earn profit!
Why not?!
Because it's the law,
and without law,
society would descend
into chaos.
If you ask me, this
society could use
a little chaos.
Not if I have anything
to say about it!
Gee, I wish Father
were alive.
Then it would be
just like old times,
sitting around the family table,
eating tube grubs,
discussing important issues
of the day.
( sighs )
Mother...
I know you're not
like other females.
You like to think about things.
You have opinions.
Is that a compliment
or an accusation?
It's a fact!
But what's also a fact
is if you don't imprint
this confession,
you'll be sold
into indentured servitude,
and I'll be forced
to make restitution.
But, Brother, it's only
three bars of latinum.
And I'm not going to let those
three bars destroy this family.
If our disgrace
is made known,
do you think
we can ever
do business
with another Ferengi again?
I wouldn't do business with me.
Mother!
Please!
For our family's reputation...
for your sons'
financial future...
please, imprint
the confession.
I can't.
I wish you could
understand, Quark.
I understand perfectly.
You're a selfish female
who never cared
about this family
about Father
or about me.
Oh...
I see you haven't changed
your bedroom, Moogie.
It's still very...
traditional.
I keep it this way
to remind myself
how idiotic Ferengi
tradition can be
when it comes to females.
Oh.
Rom, is something wrong?
Wrong? No.
Not... really.
Except... your clothes.
Would you feel more comfortable
if I took them off?
Well... maybe...
just a little.
All right, if it will
make you feel better.
But only for you.
Better?
Much!
( sighs )
( slaps her leg )
You know, Moogie...
it really would mean
a lot to Quark
if you imprint that confession.
He's made that quite clear.
I know he can be
headstrong
and overbearing,
not to mention mean...
and insulting and rude,
but he's not all bad.
He works hard.
You should see
the bar.
It's thriving.
I'd like to.
But Ferengi tradition doesn't
allow females to travel.
Quark doesn't make the rules.
He just lives
by them.
Like a good Ferengi.
Like an unenlightened Ferengi.
Oh, Moogie, can't you give back
the three bars of latinum?
If you don't, you're going
to destroy everything
Quark's
worked for.
You always were a good boy.
I don't think Quark knows
how lucky he is
to have a brother
as loyal as you.
He knows.
He just doesn't like showing it.
If you cooperate with the FCA,
I bet I can convince him
to increase your stipend.
This isn't about money, Rom.
Quark has always been more
than generous with my stipend.
I have more than enough
to live on.
If it's not about money,
then what is it about?
It's about pride.
And knowing I'm just as capable
of earning profit as any male.
Don't you see?
If I imprint that confession,
I'll be admitting that
what I did was wrong.
I'm not going to do that.
I'd rather be sold
into servitude.
But what about Quark?
He's a
smart boy.
He can take care of himself.
Enough about your brother.
Let me see your teeth.
My teeth?
Why?
They're looking
a little dull.
Why don't you
sit here
and I'll sharpen them for you?
Here we are.
Oh, Moogie...
you're the best.
( sharpener buzzing )
( Rom groans with pleasure )
Oh!
Pardshay, don't
be an idiot.
Go get an antigrav sled
before you hurt yourself.
Why don't you
just beam it to your cargo hold?
Well, I wish I
could, but it's
unstable biomatter.
Oh, the transporter should
still be able to handle it,
as long as you adjust your
phase-transition inhibitor.
Provided I had a Mark
VII transporter.
You're still using
a Mark VI?
A Mark V.
Ah, a Mark V.
I thought they, ah,
stopped making those things...
15 years ago.
But when you're working
for the Petarians,
you have to make due with
what they give you.
Oh, let me guess...
Commander Sisko.
Benjamin.
Kasidy.
Kasidy Yates.
Yes, I know.
My son has told me
a lot about you.
Well, I think Jake
fancies himself something
of a matchmaker.
He means well.
He does get a little too
enthusiastic now and then.
( crashing )
Oh, damn, that sounds
like the inertium ore.
I better go see
what's going on.
I'll give you a hand.
I can take care of it.
Of course.
Sorry about Jake.
How about coffee?
Say tomorrow evening,
1800 hours?
Sounds good.
I'll see you tomorrow.
( groaning )
( yawning )
There's nothing like
sleeping in your old room.
So, how was
your night?
Mother's been busy.
Really? I didn't even know
she was up yet.
I mean
she's been busy.
I've been doing some checking.
This isn't about
three bars of latinum.
You mean
she earned more?
A lot more.
So much that I
haven't been able
to track it all down.
She's been operating
under dozens
of different aliases,
conducting transactions
all over
the Ferengi Alliance.
Do you know what this means?
It means Moogie's got
the lobes for business.
Even if I sold
everything I have,
I couldn't come close to paying
back what she's earned.
I'm ruined.
Brother?
I-I-Is everything all right?
Mm-hmm.
Oh...
I'm so proud of you, Quark.
I mean, other people
in your situation
might overreact and
lose their temper,
make a bad situation worse.
But not my brother. Hmm.
You're too smart for that.
You're going to sit there
and study the problem,
and then come up with
a clear, simple solution.
I already have.
Oh, you see?
I told you.
What is it?
I'm going to kill her.
( yells ):
Moogie!
Aha!
Caught you.
Give me that.
Give you what?
That padd you just hid.
It's a letter
to your cousin Stol.
Likely story.
Mm-hmm, I knew it.
You were trying
to hide more profits.
Well, it won't work.
I know all about your
little financial empire.
It's not so little.
Then you admit it?
Brother, calm down.
I'm sure Moogie has
a perfectly good explanation
for what she's done.
Don't you, Moogie?
Since when
does a Ferengi
have to make excuses
for making profit?
You're a female.
And when it comes to profit,
this female is a better Ferengi
than you'll ever be!
You expect me
to believe you did
all this on your own?
Oh, you had help.
Admit it.
Tell me his name.
I'll see to it the FCA
hangs him by his lobes
in the Sacred Marketplace.
Quark, sometimes you can be
so thickheaded.
Now, Moogie, there's no need
to be insulting.
Of course there is.
Insults are
the only thing he understands.
He's so blind with jealousy,
he can't even think straight.
Me?
Jealous of you?
Ho, ho.
You're just
like your father.
Why would Father
be jealous of you?
Because he knew
I had the lobes for business,
and he didn't.
I tried to help him--
give him financial advice--
but he wouldn't listen to me,
because I was a female.
What other reason
did he need?
Females don't belong
in business.
Give me one reason why not.
Because it's wrong.
You're going to have
to do better than that.
No I'm not.
It's the law.
That was good
enough for Father,
and it's good
enough for me.
A lot of things were good enough
for your father.
He was a lobeless failure!
And if you're not careful,
you're going to end up
just like him!
That does it!
ROM:
Brother, where
are you going?
To the FCA.
Let's see
what they
have to say
about your financial empire.
Brother, wait.
Out of my way, Rom.
No, I'm not going to
let you hurt Mother.
She's no mother
of mine.
Why? Because of what
she said about Father?
Did it ever occur to you
that she might be right?
How dare you take her side
against Father's?!
Oh, don't tell
me about Father.
I knew him a lot
better than you did.
You went off
as soon as you
reached the Age
of Ascension,
but I stayed here
for ten more years.
Oh!
And you know what I learned
in those ten years?
I learned that Father
was no financial genius.
Take that back!
It's the truth!
( yells )
He went from one bad
deal to the next...
one failure
after another!
He couldn't hold
onto latinum
if you sewed it
into his pants!
Take that back!
No!
( yells )
Quark, Rom!
That's enough!
Let him
go!
But, Moogie!
Stop
it!
Stop it,
both of you!
If your brother wants
to go to the FCA,
let him.
But you'll get
in trouble.
I'll worry about that.
Go on. What are you
waiting for?!
( thunder cracks )
( panting )
That is the steepest
40 flights of stairs
I have ever climbed.
Seven strips of latinum
to use the elevator.
Talk about inflation.
( panting )
Huh, refined dilithium
down ten percent?
Huh.
The name's Quark.
I'm here to see
Liquidator Brunt.
Of course.
I'll tell Liquidator
Brunt you're here.
Have a seat.
How much?
Three slips.
I'll stand.
That'll be one slip.
I'll give you two
for the chair.
( sighs )
If you're here
to deliver
an imprinted confession,
you can leave it with me.
I'll see that
Liquidator
Brunt gets it.
Tell Brunt
I need to talk to him now.
I have information
that could shake
the very foundation
of the Ferengi Alliance.
Brother,
wait!
( panting )
I have to
sit down.
Uh-uh!
That'll be three slips
of latinum.
Brother... can you loan me...?
Yeah, yeah.
Here.
Now what do you want?
I have a message from Moogie.
There's nothing she could say
that would interest me.
She'll share it with you.
What was that?
Her profits, 50-50.
Tell Brunt I'll
talk to him later.
Come on.
Let's try out
that elevator.
But it's so
expensive.
I can afford it.
For your trouble.
Mother, I want
to apologize
for all the terrible
things I said.
I was angry and I
got carried away.
I'm sorry.
Apology accepted.
I'm just glad Rom
was able to catch you
before you made
a horrible mistake.
It would have
been a shame
to waste all
of that profit.
I'm glad
we agree.
So...
how much latinum have you made?
Does it matter?
I just want to make sure that
everything is divided fairly.
Divided?!
50-50, just like you said.
I never said that.
You said he'd let me keep
all the profit
for myself!
I said no such thing.
So I lied...
to both of you.
I had no choice.
It was the only way
to get the two of
you talking again.
There's nothing to say!
Don't get your lobes caught
in the door on your way out!
ROM:
That's enough
bickering!
You're both acting
like children!
BOTH:
Who do you think...?
I will not stand by
and let this family fall apart!
Quark, you should be ashamed
of yourself.
I've seen you
treat Cardassians
with more respect
than you show
your own mother.
And, Moogie...
if Quark can uncover
your hidden investments,
eventually the FCA will, too!
And then all that profit
will be lost.
Think about that
for a moment.
Now, neither of you
is going to leave this room
until you've settled things!
Is that
clear?!
( shouting ):
And no shouting!
I'm going to take a nap.
He's a sweet boy.
That's easy
for you to say.
He doesn't live
next door to you.
You're too hard on him.
You always have been.
I had to be.
You were always too easy on him.
Maybe if you pushed him
a little bit harder,
he would have amounted
to something.
I doubt it.
When it comes to business,
he's a lot like your father.
You enjoy insulting Father,
don't you?
I'm not
insulting
anyone.
I'm just being honest.
Rom's a lot like his father.
And you...
I suppose, are a lot like me.
I never knew you felt like that.
Your father
might have bought you
your first copy
of The Rules of Acquisition,
but who helped you
memorize them?
You did.
I don't think
I've ever been prouder...
than the first time you made it
through all 285 Rules
without
a mistake.
Rom knows them
just as well as I do.
But you understand them.
Rom never did.
And neither
did his father.
But even if Keldar
didn't know
the first thing
about profit,
he knew everything
about family.
He was a good
husband...
and a wonderful father.
And I loved him
for that--
the way
I love Rom...
and the way I love you.
You mean that?
Yes, I suppose I do.
If it'll make you happy...
I'll give back the money.
You'll imprint the confession?
You're my son, Quark.
How can I refuse you?
You don't know how
much this means to me.
I know exactly how
much this means to you.
( both laughing )
Oh, Moogie...
I love you.
There's no place
like New Orleans
for simple pleasures--
good food, great music.
Hmm. Sounds like a
great place to grow up.
The best.
Can I get you
another raktajino?
Uh, no, I'm... fine.
You seem a little
preoccupied.
It's just, when we
made our plans,
I forgot, uh... I had
a previous engagement.
I see.
Oh, it's not what you think.
It's kind of a
family obligation.
You see, my youngest brother,
he's a colonist on Cestus III.
That's on the other side
of the Federation.
Well, it's
so far away
it takes two weeks
for a subspace transmission
to get here,
and I'm expecting one tonight.
I promised my brother
I'd listen to it as it came in.
I hope nothing's wrong.
Oh, not unless he
hurt himself again.
Last time, he tore some
ligaments in his knee.
How'd that
happen?
Uh...
he was doing something
called "sliding
into second."
S-s...
sliding into second?
Yes.
That sounds like baseball.
You know about baseball?
It's my favorite sport.
But no one has played it
for 200 years.
Well, they're playing it
on Cestus III.
At least, they have been
for the last six months.
I had no idea.
That's fantastic!
How many teams are there?
Uh, six, but they're trying
to organize a couple more.
I... I didn't know
you liked baseball.
I didn't know anyone else liked
baseball except me and Jake.
Uh, look, this transmission
I mentioned
uh, it's an audio recording
of a game
between my brother's team,
the Pike City Pioneers
and the Cestus Comets.
Uh... well, if you'd like,
you're welcome to listen
to it with me.
Well, I'd...
I'd love to.
Oh, great.
Well...
Oh...
Tell me, does your
brother's league
use a designated
hitter rule?
Oh, no, they thought
about it,
but decided
against it.
Ah. Wood bats or
polyduranide?
Wood, of course.
Do you think your
brother could use
a right-handed
pitcher?
( laughing ):
Oh, no.
BRUNT:
Everything seems
to be in order.
I'm glad we can finally
put an end to this matter.
I certainly hope you
have learned
your lesson.
( sweetly ):
And what would that be?
She's speaking to me again.
No, she
wasn't.
She's speaking to me.
Now, what were you
saying about a lesson?
Ah, the lesson is:
No one can outsmart
the FCA.
I think she's
certainly
learned that.
Your mother's confession
will serve as a warning
to females
all over the Alliance.
Oh, I don't think
anyone has to
know about this.
After all, what
would people say
if they knew
a female had earned...
that much latinum?
I shudder to think.
( laughs )
Good-bye.
I sincerely hope I never see
any of you again.
The feeling is mutual.
( laughs )
( laughing sarcastically )
I thought he'd never leave.
Mother... must you?
Quark, I've just given
up a sizable fortune.
I'm in no mood
for your nagging.
You're absolutely right.
If you want to wear clothes,
go ahead.
What do I care?
I'm leaving, anyway.
So soon?
I have to reopen the bar.
It's supporting all of us now.
Well, you know, you
could call your mother
every once in a while...
maybe even visit.
I will.
I promise.
Let's go, Rom.
I'll be along
in a moment, Brother.
I'm glad to see
you two
are finally
getting along.
Yeah, I think
things will be
a lot better between
us from now on.
As long as he
doesn't find out
you only gave
the FCA
a third
of your profits.
If you ask me, a
third was too much.
Well, it's
my own fault
for not hiding
it better.
You sure the FCA
won't find the rest?
I've got it
hidden so well,
I'll be lucky
if I can find it.
( both chuckle )
Oh, Moogie...
Now, Rom, don't start crying.
You'll get me doing it.
Go on, go on.
Quark's
waiting for you.
Take good care of your brother.