COMPUTER: The Cardassians
are still closing.
They have powered
their weapon systems.
( Nog sighing )
( console beeping )
They have established
weapons lock.
Weapons lock broken.
( laughs )
Going to warp.
( knocking )
Get out of here, Jake!
I'm-I'm in the middle
of a simulation!
I said get out of here!
Computer, end program.
Oh! Oh, oh!
You okay?
Look what you
made me do.
Well, you should know
not to end a program
sitting down.
Why did you come in here?
You were supposed to meet
me half an hour ago.
Well, I didn't realize
it had gotten so late.
Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
How's it going, anyway?
Pretty good, I've
improved my reaction time
by almost 20 percent
but I've got to get it up
another five.
Is that the cutoff point
for getting into the Academy
Preparatory Program?
Exactly.
Don't worry about it, Nog.
You'll get there.
I'd better.
Because if I don't
get into the program,
I'll never be admitted
into the Academy next year.
You think six weeks
of summer classes
will make the difference?
If I do well.
I have to show
the admissions committee
how determined I am
to become a cadet.
Don't worry so much, Nog.
You'll be a great cadet.
In the meantime,
you make a lousy stock boy.
Why can't you take after
your friend here?
He knows enough
to stay out of Starfleet.
Even a human can see
there's a lot more
profitable opportunities
out there for a young man
with ambition.
Uncle, he wants
to be a writer.
There's no profit in that.
On the contrary,
writing holosuite programs--
especially the more
intimate variety--
is very profitable.
I'll bet.
I'll tell you what.
The two of you come up
with a proposal,
and I'll put up the latinum
for your
first program.
I don't think so, Uncle.
QUARK:
All right, fine...
join Starfleet.
I don't know why I bother
trying to help you anyway.
Go down to the storeroom
and get your father.
Tell him to get
behind the bar.
Lieutenant Dax has asked me
to join the senior staff
for a very important
meeting in the wardroom.
Do you have any idea
what Dax wants to
talk to us about?
No.
Apparently, she asked
Leeta to come as well.
Hmm. I've noticed
they've been spending
quite a bit
of time together.
Do you keep tabs on
everybody, Constable?
Not everyone.
But really, Doctor,
two Delvin fluff pastries
for breakfast this morning?
You of all people
should know better
than to start
your day like that.
( laughs )
( quiet conversations )
Major. Chief.
Hello, Leeta
Oh, hello.
And how are you doing?
Thank you all for coming.
BASHIR:
No problem.
O'BRIEN:
What's up?
I'll get
right to the point.
You are the seven people
on this station
that I feel closest to,
and I want you all to be
a part of my zhian'tara.
Zhian'tara,
what's that?
It's the Trill rite of closure.
I've read about it.
DAX:
The zhian'tara
is a ritual
where joined Trills
get a chance
to actually meet
their previous hosts.
Meet them-- how?
That's where
you come in.
If you don't mind, I'd
like to borrow your bodies
for a few hours.
What do you mean,
"borrow" our bodies?
DAX:
Well, if you agree
to participate,
the memories of one
of my previous hosts
will be temporarily removed
from the symbiont
and imprinted onto you.
You essentially become
one of my hosts
for the duration
of the ritual.
And how is this
accomplished?
The memories are transferred
telepathically by a Guardian.
A Guardian?
LEETA:
They take care of
the symbionts.
Usually, they're unjoined Trill.
Leeta is sort of an
amateur sociologist.
It comes in handy
in my line of work.
You never know who you'll meet
at the dabo table.
You're asking me
to hand my body over
to some dead person.
Only for a few hours.
Uh-huh. What happens
to me in the meantime?
You'll remain
conscious
of everything that's
going on around you.
And at any time, you can
reassert yourself
and regain control
of your body.
But it's best to relax
and let the host's
memories emerge.
The point is to give
Jadzia a chance
to interact with
her previous hosts.
Curzon spoke very fondly
of his zhian'tara.
He said it was one
of the most powerful
experiences of his life.
I do have one question.
What about Joran?
Joran... wasn't he
the, uh, crazy host of yours--
the musician
who killed someone?
Uh, Commander Sisko has
volunteered to embody Joran.
We've already discussed
taking certain precautions
during the transfer.
Well, count me in.
Me, too.
Yes.
Agreed.
Chief?
Oh, yes, yeah, I'm in.
Why is everybody looking at me?
Because you're the only one who
hasn't agreed to participate.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
You're going to have
to find someone else.
I really want you to be
a part of this, Quark.
I was hoping that you
would embody Audrid for me.
Well...
I think it will
make us closer.
Uh... when you put it
that way...
DAX:
I knew I could
count on you.
Kira, I would like
you to embody Lela
my first host.
We'll start tomorrow
after the Guardian
arrives.
It means a lot to me
that all of you are
willing to do this.
Thank you.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but did Quark just agree
to embody one
of your female hosts?
Yes, he did.
Hmm.
After that, comes the deductive
reasoning portion of the exam
and then the spatial
orientation test.
The whole thing should
take about four days.
Now, I know it must sound
overwhelming to you.
Just try to take it
one day at a time.
One day at a time, right.
And today, all you
have to worry about
is the stress
reaction test.
Computer, run
program delta 5 9.
I-I thought this was going
to be a runabout simulation.
No.
But... that's what I practiced.
Well, if we tested you
where you practiced,
it wouldn't exactly be
stressful, now would it?
Man your post.
You're the Operations
Officer on duty.
( rumbling )
What was that?!
( console beeping )
You tell me.
We've been
trying to get Dax
back to the homeworld
to perform the zhian'tara
for some time now.
She kept putting us off,
so the Symbiosis Commission
decided to force the issue
and send me here.
I just haven't had time
to get away.
You could have
made the time.
Where is the zhian'tara
to take place?
I have preparations
to make.
This way.
I'nora, ja'kala Dax...
zhian'shee, Lela tanus rem.
Gon'dar, Jadzia tor.
Jadzia, zhian'tara vok.
Tu Dax, zhian'tani ress.
Zhian'par, Lela garu'koj...
Kira?
No...
Lela.
You must be Dax's new host.
I'm Jadzia.
Oh, what a beautiful name.
I have a few questions
for both of you.
I need to make sure
the memory transference
is complete.
Go ahead.
What is the last thing
you remember?
Talking to Curzon
at his zhian'tara.
Can you tell me
the name of the person
who supervised Lela
when she was an initiate?
No, I can't remember.
Well, that's
perfectly all right.
It just means Lela's memories
have been temporarily
removed from your mind.
It's a little
disorienting,
like part of me
is suddenly missing.
Not missing--
right here--
and the name of my initiate
supervisor was Jobel.
Excellent, the transference
seems to be complete.
Unless either of you
have any questions,
I'll leave you alone
for a few hours.
Thank you.
( door opens, closes )
Such odd fellows
these Guardians are.
I know.
Well, it's understandable,
I suppose.
They spend most
of their time underground,
tending symbiont pools
full of this stuff.
Ah, I love the smell of it.
Don't you?
It looks like you've ended up
a long way from home, Jadzia.
What is it?
It's just, uh... I hold
my hands behind my back...
the same way you do.
Ah, it's a habit I picked up
when I was a legislator.
I was one of the first women
to serve as a council member.
When I started out,
I talked with my hands a lot,
lots of emphatic gesturing.
I discovered
some of my male colleagues
were imitating me,
so I started to do this.
I just thought it was
an unconscious habit.
I never realized why I did it.
Ah, that's the point
of a zhian'tara--
to discover these things
about yourself.
It's so strange.
It's like you really are Lela.
Well, in a sense, I am.
After all, what is a person
but a sum of their memories?
Oh...
I have a feeling that
these next few days
are going to be
extraordinary for you.
( sighs )
Tobin, I don't think
Chief O'Brien
is going to appreciate
you biting his nails.
Sorry.
I guess I'm
a little nervous.
That's all right.
I get that way
sometimes myself.
And now you know
who you have
to thank for it.
Sorry.
Will you please stop
saying you're sorry?
Sorry.
I've been working on
finishing your proof
of Fermat's Last Theorem.
You have?!
It's the most original
approach to the proof...
since Wiles, over 300 years ago.
Thanks.
I guess I
tend to look
for original approaches myself.
I guess I have you
to thank for that as well.
( clapping )
Very nice.
This is an
excellent body
you managed
to get for me.
I'll be sure
to pass that along.
I remember when I first
got the Dax symbiont.
I was worried that it might
affect my coordination
in some way.
And hurt your gymnastics career.
As it turned out,
being joined
improved my concentration.
Really? I found
that as well.
You're a gymnast?
No, but I'm
an expert
in Klingon
martial arts.
Oh.
Did you take it up
before or after
you were joined?
After.
Why am I not surprised?
( in a soft, sweet voice):
Sit right here, and I'll
tell you all about it.
The day I was named head
of the Symbiosis Commission
was one of the happiest
of my life.
Right behind the day I gave
birth to my first child.
Are you a mother, Jadzia?
No.
Oh... I hope you
will be someday.
There's nothing quite like
holding a baby to your breast,
nursing it...
The entity that lent me
this body wishes to speak.
( normally ):
How much longer am I
going to have to do this?
Another hour at most.
And the sooner
we get back to it,
the sooner
it'll be over.
Just remember, not a word
about this to anyone.
I promise.
Maybe you should go easy
on those, Torias.
Julian was just telling me
the other day
he's started
to watch what he eats.
Well, you should tell
your friend to live a little.
Life's too short
to deprive yourself
of the simple pleasures.
I should know.
You didn't exactly
deprive yourself.
No, but my life was too short.
The accident.
Still, I'm lucky.
I continue to exist,
as part of you,
just as Jadzia
will go on existing
when the symbiont
is passed on to a new host.
We're part of something
bigger than any one of us.
I just feel lucky
to have been chosen.
So do I.
( door chimes )
Come in.
It's late.
I think it's time we returned
Dr. Bashir's body to him.
It was nice meeting you.
I'm ready.
Are you sure about this,
Commander?
Don't worry, Odo.
Joran isn't going to be able
to hurt anyone
from inside of a holding cell.
There's just one problem.
You're going to be
in there with him.
Hmm.
Activate the force field.
Joran.
( high, melodic voice):
Hello, Jadzia.
If you need me,
I'll be right outside.
As will I.
It's good to see you again,
Jadzia.
Tell me, have you been
practicing your music?
Yes, when I have the time.
Good.
Do you think of me
when you play?
Sometimes.
I'm glad.
You're a very
pretty girl, Jadzia.
Very pretty.
But unfortunately,
that's all you are.
You're nothing
compared to
Lela, Torias,
or myself.
You're a pretender.
You must realize that by now.
You don't know
anything about me.
Only what I can see.
A little girl, not worthy
of the noble creature
nestled inside her.
You're overwhelmed by it.
You're in over your head.
( snickers )
And they said
it was a mistake
choosing me for joining.
But there is one hope
for you, Jadzia,
and that's me.
My strength is within you.
You don't have
to be afraid of it.
I'm not.
Then let me
show you
how to use it.
Lower the force field, Jadzia.
Lower it...
and you will never have to be
afraid of anything ever again.
No.
Joran!
Stop it.
You're hurting him!
Benjamin,
take control!
( normally ): I think that's
enough of Joran for now.
Are you all right?
JORAN:
Surprise.
( normally ):
It's all right, old man.
It's me.
( panting )
Whoo!
Thanks.
For what?
For not breaking any bones.
PATRONS:
Dabo!
Will you stop doing that?
It's very distracting.
I'm trying to do the books.
I can't help it.
My son's future is being decided
at this very minute.
Well, pacing around
like some Alvanian cave sloth
isn't going to help him.
What's that?
Uh... a cadet's uniform.
I got it for Nog.
I had Garak make it to order.
It cost five strips of latinum.
Well, you wasted
your money.
He's not going to need it.
Why not?
Because...
he'll be issued a uniform
if and when he gets
to the Academy.
Well, now he'll have two.
I keep thinking about Joran.
I heard what he told you.
I can't seem to get
it out of my head.
Jadzia, did you put off
having your zhian'tara
because you were afraid
you wouldn't measure up
to the other hosts?
I don't know,
maybe I did.
Now that it's almost over,
I hope you realize
you were wrong.
I'm not so sure I was.
I don't understand
how you could say that.
You were chosen for joining
because you deserved it,
just as much
as any of the others.
If that's true,
then why did Curzon
wash me
out of the initiate program?
You tell me.
I've always believed
it was because he
wanted to challenge me
so that I would reapply
and try harder.
Now I'm not so sure.
Why not?
That's exactly
what you did.
Maybe Curzon just didn't
think I was good enough.
I find that hard to believe.
But if that's
what you're afraid of,
why don't you ask him
when you see him?
I will...
but what if he tells me
something I don't
want to hear?
I have to go.
Jadzia, zhian'tara vok.
Tu Dax, zhian'tani ress.
Zhian'par, Odo garu'koj...
I'm going to my office
for a while.
Benjamin!
You do recognize me,
don't you?
Curzon?
Don't tell me,
the nose gave me away, huh?
( laughs )
What's the matter?
Aren't you happy to see me?
Of course.
So, where's Jadzia?
Ah, it's all right.
I told her I wanted
to come see you.
That we'd meet up later
at Quark's.
I'm going to give
that little toad
the scare of his life.
You sound like Odo.
I am Odo.
I don't understand.
I thought you
were Curzon.
I'm both.
The, uh, Guardian thinks
it has something to do
with my shape-shifting
nature.
It's as if Odo and Curzon
have been joined.
It's proven to be quite
an interesting experience
for both of us.
In any case,
the Guardian says
it's nothing
to worry about.
I like the beard,
by the way.
Yeah?
Absolutely.
So... when is Kasidy Yates
coming back, huh?
Huh?
Not you, too.
Well, she's a fine-looking
woman, Ben.
Reminds me of the girl
you took up with on Pelios...
Why don't we join
Jadzia in Quark's?
And let Jake
finish his homework.
I'll tell you
all about it later.
Okay.
Curzon, remember?
( gruffly ):
Quark!
Odo?
What happened to your face?
Never mind my face.
Did I ever mention
you're a magnificent
scoundrel?
Two tranyas please,
very cold.
Right away.
It's going to take Quark
a little while
to get over that.
Jadzia.
It looks like the two of you
are having a good time.
Well, as good a time as
two gentlemen can have
without the
company of a lady.
Please, join us.
Excuse me while I slip into
something more appropriate.
Ah!
( laughs )
I love being a changeling.
SISKO:
Well, if you two
don't mind, I think
I'll be pushing off.
Benjamin, don't go.
I have to finish evaluating
Nog's test results.
He's waiting
to hear how he did.
Thanks for stopping by,
old man.
It was good to see you.
Oh!
Well, there goes
the best friend I ever had.
Well?
So... are you enjoying
your zhian'tara?
For the most part.
What about that Tobin, huh?
Did he tell you that I got him
drunk for the first time
during my zhian'tara?
( laughing ):
No.
But I can see why you did.
Curzon, there's something
I want to talk to you about.
Oh?
Do you remember when
I was an initiate?
Do you see that
Ferengi over there?
A bulletin came in
on him last week.
He's a tongo hustler.
I'd love to clean him out.
We should get a game going.
( laughs )
Tongo!
I just don't
understand
how I could have
failed, Father.
You've always been so good
with spatial orientation.
Remember the time
we redid the floors
and you managed
to stack all the chairs
so they fit
behind the bar?
Now I won't qualify
to take the Academy
Entrance Exam.
My Starfleet
career is over
before it even started.
QUARK:
He's right,
you know.
And it's not fair.
Starfleet has no idea
who it's passing up.
Nog, you would have
made a good officer.
I want you
to know something.
There will always be
a place for you here--
at Quark's.
Sorry, Lonzo.
Excuse me, folks,
but the bar has been closed
for over an hour now.
I asked you nicely before,
but if you don't leave,
I'm going to have
to call Security.
I am Security.
Don't worry,
Quark.
We're going.
( grumbling )
( Odo/Curzon sighs
and chuckles )
I confiscated this
from a Yridian smuggler.
Don't you need it for evidence?
Bah!
I still want to talk to you
about what happened
when I was an initiate.
I know you do.
So...
What is it you
want to ask me?
Why didn't you object
when you heard I was
reinstated into the program?
I don't know, Jadzia.
Maybe I decided I'd
been too hard on you.
It was your job to be hard
on initiates.
Yes, but...
( sighs )
The truth is
I felt sorry for you.
Well, you wanted
to be joined so badly.
You were so young, so lovely.
I guess I've always had
this nagging feeling
I didn't have
your complete confidence.
I-I tried to push it aside,
but now it turns out
I was right.
You never thought I was
good enough to be a host.
Whatever I may have thought
doesn't matter.
You are a host.
Isn't that enough?
No.
I feel like I don't
have your respect,
and I'm afraid
when your memories
are restored to me,
I'm going to feel
like I don't respect myself.
In that case,
you'll be happy to know
that I've come to a decision
that's going to benefit
both of us.
What do you mean?
I've decided to stay
where I am, in this body.
And I'm not just
speaking as Curzon.
This is Odo's decision as well.
We like what we've become,
and neither of us wants to go
back to the way things were.
Ahh!
( chuckling )
There's no way to remove
Curzon's memories from Odo
without his cooperation.
He has to give
them up willingly.
What'll happen
to Jadzia
if we can't
persuade him?
It'll take
some time for her
to adjust
to the new balance,
but she'll be fine.
Do you want me to
talk to Curzon?
I know him better than anyone.
I might be able to get him
to cooperate.
I don't think so.
I don't think
I want to do anything.
What do you mean?
I mean I'm fine.
And obviously, Odo and Curzon
are well-suited to each other.
Maybe it's better this way.
I'd like to speak to Jadzia
alone for a moment.
Do you really want to leave
things as they are?
Or are you just trying
to avoid a confrontation
with Curzon?
You once told me
that Curzon intimidated you
when you were an initiate.
I looked up to him.
I still do.
( sighs )
Maybe that's why
I find it hard
to challenge
his decisions.
Let me tell you
something about Curzon.
He was my friend,
he was
my confidant.
In a way, he was
my teacher as well,
but he was also manipulative,
selfish, and arrogant.
Most people let him
get away with it
because he was so charming.
Sometimes, I let him
get away with it, too,
but, from time to time,
he'd push me too far,
and I'd have
to stand up to him,
tell him he'd
crossed the line.
And how would he react?
Sometimes, he'd just laugh
and admit it.
Sometimes, he'd be furious.
But either way, he'd back off
because he knew he was wrong.
And he is wrong now.
He's being selfish,
and he's manipulated you
to get you
to go along
with what he wants.
Now...
are you going to confront him
or let him get away with it?
It's up to you.
I know what you did.
Take it easy.
What's wrong with you?
You know what's wrong.
You reconfigured
the holosuite
so that Nog would fail
the spatial
orientation test.
I did it for his
own good, Rom.
I couldn't just stand by
and watch my nephew
throw his life away.
You had no right
to interfere!
I've already told Commander
Sisko what you did,
and he's going to let
Nog retake the test.
You what?
You heard me.
And if you ever
do anything
to hurt Nog again,
I'll burn the bar
to the ground.
You wouldn't dare.
Oh, yes, I would.
My son's happiness
is more important to me
than anything,
even latinum!
Remember that, Brother!
Jadzia.
Come in, come in.
( chuckles )
I was just oozing
around the room.
You have no idea
what a liberating
experience it is
to be in a liquid state.
We need to talk.
All right.
What is it you want
to talk about?
I want my memories back.
Ah...
I'm sorry.
I realize this is
difficult for you,
but you'll get over it.
Trust me, it's
better this way.
For you, maybe.
You're both living out a life
you never could have
had otherwise.
But it's my life
you're living.
Those should be my memories.
Not anymore.
Maybe they never
should have been.
That's where
you're wrong.
I earned the right to be joined.
I am the only person
in our planet's history
who was ever readmitted
to the initiate program
after being washed out.
The only reason
you got back in
was because I felt
sorry for you.
Curzon was famous
for rejecting initiates.
Why feel sorry for me?
Now don't you use that tone
of voice with me, little girl.
You can't intimidate me, Curzon.
And I'm not
a little girl anymore.
( sighs )
No.
I suppose you're not.
The truth is
you weren't a little girl
back when you were an initiate.
You were a brilliant
and beautiful young woman.
Very beautiful.
You were in love with me?
At first...
I thought it was just
an old man's
passing infatuation.
After all, I'd always
had an eye for the ladies.
But as we spent
more time together,
I started to realize
it was something...
deeper.
Then why were you
so hard on me?
I couldn't let you
know the truth.
You were an initiate.
I was your supervisor.
So you washed me out
of the program.
Later, I realized
that I'd robbed you
of something you'd
wanted all your life.
I felt so guilty,
I nearly retired
from the Symbiosis
Commission.
So when I reapplied,
you didn't object.
On the contrary.
I was grateful
when you reapplied.
It let me off the hook.
So, now that you know,
you can see that it's best
for both of us
that I stay here in this body.
Why?
Because you loved me?
Because I still love you.
There's no shame
in that, Curzon.
Yes, there is.
And if we rejoin,
you'll feel it, too.
No, I won't...
because I love you.
You're a part of me,
and I want you back.
That way, Jadzia and
Curzon can be together
the way they should be...
through Dax.
( dart board beeping )
He's coming!
( Rom panting )
He's coming.
( sighs )
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to introduce
Starfleet's...
future...
my son, Nog.
Congratulations, Nog.
Thank you, sir.
Yeah, way to go.
I'm afraid
you've jumped the gun
putting on that uniform.
I know I haven't earned
the right to wear it yet,
but my father got it for me.
Hopefully,
you'll get to put on
the real one next year.
When you ace the Academy
Entrance Exam.
Yeah.
What's the matter,
Chief?
It just occurred to me.
As soon as that kid
graduates from the Academy,
I'm going to have
to call him "sir."
Okay.
What can I
get you, Nog?
Oh.
A root beer.
It's an Earth drink--
something they serve
at the Academy.
A root beer.
This is the end
of Ferengi civilization.
May I join you,
Lieutenant?
Of course.
( sighs )
I'd just like to apologize
for my behavior
while I was joined
with Curzon.
There's no need to apologize.
In a way, I'm glad it happened.
It forced me to deal
with some things
about myself
I've never really faced.
Besides, you've...
given me a special gift.
Oh?
You see...
now I have Curzon's memories
of what it felt like
to be a changeling.
I never realized
how much joy it gives you.
And I never understood
how much joy
you humanoids experience
in things like eating, drinking,
staying up all night playing
tongo.
( chuckling )
Frankly, I don't
see how Curzon
ever managed to get
any work done.
He always seemed to somehow.
Well...
he must have been
a remarkable man.
Yes, he is.