Commander's Log,
Stardate 48959.1.
It is with mixed emotions
that I record this
my final Commander's Log.
The last three years
have been
the most demanding
and rewarding of my career.
I can only hope
that the future will hold
even greater challenges.
Dad, there's something
I've been wanting
to say to you for a long time.
And now that I
finally have the chance,
I'm going to make it
short and simple.
Congratulations...
Captain Sisko.
Well, now that you have
another pip on your collar,
does that mean
I can't disagree
with you anymore?
No, it just means
I'm never wrong.
Oh, we'll see about that.
Curzon would have been
proud of you,
but not as proud as I am.
That means a lot to me, Dax.
Though I don't
fully understand
this humanoid obsession
with rank and title,
if anyone deserves
to be promoted, it's you.
Thank you, Constable.
Well, as someone who is
obsessed with rank and title
congratulations, Captain.
That goes for
me, too, Captain.
This calls
for a toast.
BASHIR: That better not be
from a replicator, Quark.
Chateau Cleon, 2303.
I already put it
on your account.
Can I?
I guess a sip
won't hurt.
Well...
Here's to the newest and
best Captain in Starfleet,
and all I can say is,
it's about time.
Hear, hear.
Cheers.
Ah, ah, that's,
that's enough.
Thanks for coming, Ambassador.
Those pips look good
on you, Captain.
Though, to be honest,
I'm not really here
for the ceremony.
I had that feeling.
What can I do for you?
Our intelligence
reports indicate
there's been a coup d'état
on the Tzenkethi homeworld.
I doubt anyone is going
to miss the Autarch.
I know I won't.
Unfortunately, it's too early
to tell who's in control,
but we don't want
to take any chances.
We need to remind the Tzenkethi
that the Federation
is committed to protecting
our colonies
near their border.
You want to show the flag.
Exactly.
The Defiant will leave in two
days on a week-long patrol.
I'll be coming along
as an observer.
I've heard a lot
about the Defiant.
I'm looking forward
to seeing her in operation.
I don't think
you'll be disappointed.
She's a fine ship.
With a fine crew.
Now what do you say we
get back to the party?
Of course.
ALL:
♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For he's
a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ Which nobody can deny. ♪
O'BRIEN:
Hip, hip...
ALL:
Hooray!
Hip, hip...
( applause )
I want a complete overhaul
of the deflector
shield generators
and targeting sensors.
Oh, yes-- take on
a full complement
of photon torpedoes.
Don't worry, Captain.
If the Tzenkethi
try to start any trouble,
we'll be ready for them.
I don't doubt it, Chief.
( clattering and thumping )
Captain?
( sighs )
Getting jumpy
in your old age, O'Brien.
SISKO: My son, the writer,
thinks I should say
something profound
on this occasion.
He even offered to write me
a brief statement.
I told him
I'd take care of it myself.
But as it turns out, the only
thing I can think of is:
Begin Captain's Log,
Stardate 48960.9.
So, have you
told her yet?
Told who?
Captain Yates.
About your
promotion.
Yeah, I barely had time
to send my father
a transmission.
In fact, I don't even
know where Kasidy is.
She's hauling a load of
duridium ore to Solais V.
Oh.
You could probably
contact her on subspace.
I'd rather tell
her in person.
When's she due back
on the station?
About a month.
A month?!
Ah, there's nothing worse
than a long-distance
relationship.
I wouldn't call it
a relationship, Dax.
I've only taken
her out once.
Okay, twice.
I think the exact
figure is three times.
She's quite
an interesting woman.
She's very independent,
a little opinionated,
but she has
a nice sense of humor.
And...?
And? What do you want
me to tell you, Dax?
That you miss her.
That you can't
wait to see her.
I don't know.
Anything.
Kira, O'Brien, Bashir,
they're all dying
of curiosity, and...
well, I have to
tell them something.
Fine. You tell them
when she gets back,
I'm going to take her
to the holosuite,
and we're going to watch
the seventh game
of the 1964 World Series.
You do like her.
Captain on the Bridge.
Ambassador.
Captain.
All stations,
report.
Helm ready.
Weapons ready.
Communications systems
standing by.
Warp and impulse engines
are on line.
Seal the airlock,
release docking clamps.
Docking clamps released.
Engage thrusters.
Clearing the station.
Lay in a course for the
Tzenkethi border, warp eight.
Aye, aye, Captain.
Engage.
( rumbling creak )
Hello?
Who's there?
( clattering thumps )
Julian!
You called me, Chief?
Why didn't you
answer me?
I had this spanner
in my mouth.
What are you doing here, anyway?
I was connecting
my new diagnostic console
to the Medical Bay's power grid.
Well, I could have
done that for you.
Oh, just putting my engineering
extension courses to work.
Besides, I know
you have your hands full.
Oh.
Where are you going now?
I'm done.
Huh.
Not bad for an extension course.
You wanted
to see me, sir?
Yes, Commander.
It's about
Ambassador Krajensky.
Please.
I know Starfleet
doesn't intend
for this to be
a combat mission.
But just in case the Tzenkethi
have other ideas,
I want make sure the Ambassador
is kept out of harm's way.
Yes, sir.
I'll see to it that,
if hostilities do occur,
the Ambassador is
escorted off the Bridge.
He won't like it.
I won't let that bother me.
Very good, Commander.
That will be all.
Captain.
I just want to say that...
I agree with
what Chief O'Brien said
about your promotion.
It's about time.
I appreciate
the sentiment, Commander,
but it really
doesn't change anything.
I have the assignment I want.
I have the crew that I want.
The rank doesn't
make much difference.
You'd be surprised.
People don't enter Starfleet
to become Commanders
or Admirals,
for that matter.
It's the Captain's chair
that everyone has their eye on.
That's what I wanted
when I joined up, but...
you don't get to be a Captain
wearing a gold uniform.
You could always transfer
from security to command.
Then who would protect
the Ambassador?
Dismissed, Mr. Eddington.
Thank you, sir.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 48962.5.
We are 12 hours
from the border.
I haven't been in this area
since the last
Federation-Tzenkethi war.
Being here brings back a lot
of memories, most of them bad.
( console beeping )
Captain, we're receiving
a priority one
distress signal
from Barisa Prime,
audio only.
Put it
through.
MALE ( staticky ):
Under heavy fire
from Tzenkethi warships.
I don't know how much
longer we can hold out.
Can anyone hear me?
This is...
( transmission cuts off )
Constable?
We've lost contact.
Try to reestablish.
It's no use, Captain.
They're gone.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've been unable
to reestablish contact
with Barisa Prime.
Therefore, I've no choice
but to assume
we are at war
with the Tzenkethi.
Lieutenant,
set a course
for Barisa Prime,
maximum warp.
I want continual scans
for Tzenkethi ships.
Constable, contact
Starfleet Command.
Let them know
what happened.
Major, what
other starships
are in this sector?
The closest one is the Ulysses.
They're studying
protoplanetary
masses
in the Hellespont Nebula.
That puts them...
20 hours away at maximum warp.
Lieutenant, transmit a message
to Captain Entebe
on the Ulysses.
ODO:
Captain, I'm
having trouble
getting through
to Starfleet Command.
There seems to be
a power fluctuation
in the communications system.
I can't get a
message out, either.
The console is
functioning normally.
The problem must be in
the transceiver assembly.
I need that system
back on line, Chief.
I'll get on it
right away.
Lieutenant, I could
use some help.
Major, take the helm.
Yes, sir.
What do you make
of this, Lieutenant?
I've never seen
anything like it.
It's spreading
through the system
like some kind of parasite.
It seems to be linked
to key points
within the
transceiver assembly.
Better get it
out of there.
( cries out )
A force field.
Come on.
Where are we going?
I want to check the
other command systems.
I have a bad
feeling about this.
SISKO: You say these things
are all over the ship?
O'BRIEN:
They've attached themselves
to the command and
communication relays,
the internal sensors,
the transporter,
the deflector
shield grid--
almost every
critical system.
Is there any way to get
past the force fields?
None that
we've found yet.
We're still
working on it.
Hmm.
Well, I guess
the question is
how did they
get aboard?
Or should I say
who placed
them here?
Well, I don't know
who did it,
but I know it
definitely happened
after we left the station.
I ran a systems check
before our departure.
They weren't
there then.
Which means someone aboard
this ship is a saboteur.
We've got 47 people on board.
Theoretically, any one of them
could have planted
those devices.
Chief?
It's nothing, sir.
It's not even worth mentioning.
It doesn't sound like you're
too sure about that.
Well, I did see someone
crawling about in one
of the Jefferies tubes
the other day.
Who?
It was Julian.
He was connecting
a medical console
to the power grid.
Which is right next
to the communications relay.
Are you accusing Julian
of sabotage?
No one's accusing anyone
of anything, I...
But I want to talk to Julian.
Wait.
I think I have a better idea.
This crew has been
through a lot together.
In fact, I would trust any
one of you with my life.
But after looking
at the evidence,
there's only one conclusion
I can draw:
Someone on this ship
is guilty of sabotage.
With your permission, Captain,
the Constable and I
can begin questioning
the crew immediately.
That won't be necessary.
Lieutenant?
We found one of the devices
planted
in the warp plasma conduit,
which means whoever put it there
would have been exposed
to trace amounts
of tetryon
particles.
And those particles would still
be detectable on the saboteur?
Yes, but not
for much longer.
They dissipate
quickly.
So you're going to scan
all the members of the crew
for tetryon particles.
Starting with the senior staff.
O'Brien and I already
scanned positive
since we opened up
the warp core controls
during our
investigation.
You realize, of course, that
if no one else tests positive...
We'll be the prime suspects.
Yes, we know that.
We might as well get started.
You're clean.
I'm glad to hear it.
Might as well
do me next.
You're okay, too.
Julian.
Hmm?
Of course.
Nothing.
You sound
relieved.
Well, I am.
After all, you were
in that conduit
the other day.
Ambassador,
if you please?
Certainly.
BASHIR:
I was never
in any conduit.
Of course you were.
I saw you there.
It's a changeling.
We've cloaked.
Lieutenant,
bring us out of warp.
Full stop...
now.
Constable, Commander...
deploy security
teams immediately.
I want that changeling found
before he can do
any more damage.
Yes, sir.
Captain, the helm's
not responding.
We're still at warp.
I can't deactivate
the cloaking device.
The weapons array is activated.
The phaser banks
are charging.
And we've got photon torpedoes
on line and ready to launch.
The ship's no longer
under our control.
Our security teams
have gone over
every centimeter
of the ship,
checked every
piece of cargo,
questioned every
crew member.
We still haven't been able
to find the changeling.
Is there any way
he could have been
transported
off the ship?
At warp?
It's unlikely, but...
with Dominion technology
I suppose
it's possible.
He's still here.
He won't leave until he's
completed his mission.
Which is?
It looks like the Dominion
is hoping to start a war
between the Federation
and the Tzenkethi.
KIRA:
Well, if you ask me,
the Tzenkethi
are doing a pretty good job
of that all by themselves.
SISKO:
Not necessarily.
The transmission
we received from Barisa Prime
could have been faked
using that device
we found implanted
in the
communications relay.
In fact, our entire
mission could have been
engineered by
the Dominion.
Think about it.
We've been all over this ship
and we have not seen a trace
of the real
Ambassador Krajensky,
nor his remains.
Which means, he was
probably replaced
before we left the station.
Maybe the real Ambassador
never came
to Deep Space 9 at all.
So everything Ambassador
Krajensky told us
could have been a lie--
the Tzenkethi
coup d'état,
increased tension
along the border,
the threat of an attack.
And now, here we are, cloaked,
armed for battle
and heading into
Tzenkethi space.
If we can't
stop this ship
before we cross
the border,
we may wind up
causing a war
rather than
preventing one.
Which is, no doubt
what my people are hoping for.
A war between the Tzenkethi
and the Federation
would destabilize
the Alpha Quadrant,
making it that much easier
for the Dominion
to move in.
EDDINGTON:
I wish the internal sensors
were on line.
It'd make it a lot easier
to track down the changeling.
ODO:
I'm not sure the
sensors would help.
If you scan me while I'm a rock,
you'll detect a rock.
I may not be able to duplicate
a humanoid perfectly,
but I'm guessing he can.
We scanned Krajensky
for tetryon particles.
He registered
as human.
KIRA:
Well then, right now,
the changeling
could be anything...
or anyone on this ship.
Then we have to narrow
his options.
Confine
all nonessential
personnel
to their quarters
and seal them in
with force fields.
Doctor, I want
you to review
all the tricorder
readings.
See if you can
find anything
that will help us
find the changeling.
And take some
security with you.
From here on, no one
is to be left alone.
We have seven hours
before we enter Tzenkethi space.
I want that changeling
found before then.
EDDINGTON:
That won't be easy.
Let's face it, no matter
how many precautions we take,
he could replace any one of us,
and we won't know it
until it's too late.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Hopefully,
this will be over soon,
and you'll be able
to return to duty.
All right, let's go.
This may take a while.
Keep your phasers
on stun
and stay calm.
I don't want anyone
getting nervous
and shooting one
of us by mistake.
You sure I can't interest
you in one of these?
I don't use them.
Besides, in the history
of my people,
no changeling has
ever harmed another.
I'd hate to be the first.
Apparently, that changeling
doesn't feel the same way.
If we don't stop him,
no one on board will escape
unharmed, including you.
You may be right.
But I've been
a security officer
most of my humanoid
existence,
and in all that time, I've
never found it necessary
to fire a weapon
or take a life.
I don't intend
to start now.
This is O'Brien.
I need a security team in
the Engine Room immediately.
It must have been
the changeling.
I went down the hall to get
an interphasic compensator.
I heard a noise,
and when I came back...
She has a severe
concussion.
Give me a hand.
We've got to get her to
the Medical Bay immediately.
Stay here
with the Chief.
Damage control team,
report to the Engine Room.
MAN: Aye, sir.
( sighs )
Dax is still
unconscious.
I've given her
cortical analeptics
to stabilize
her condition.
She should be all right
in a day or two,
but until then...
Is there any way
to speed up the process?
I could use a neural stimulator,
but that might cause
irreversible brain damage.
I don't
recommend it.
Then Chief O'Brien
is going to have
to regain control of the ship
without her.
I'm afraid so.
I should get back to my patient.
The changeling's
very clever.
Taking Dax out makes
O'Brien's job a lot harder.
One thing's for sure.
We're not going to start a war
with the Tzenkethi.
If O'Brien can't regain control
before we cross the border,
I'll have no choice
but to destroy the Defiant.
Our objective is simple.
Find the changeling
and stop him
before he can do
any more damage.
We'll break
into two-person teams.
Each team will be armed
with phaser rifles.
EDDINGTON:
Now, we've reconfigured
the rifles
to fire
an expanding energy pulse.
ODO:
Phasers have
been set
low enough to prevent
damaging equipment,
but high enough to
affect the changeling.
SISKO:
The changeling
could be hiding anywhere.
He could look like anything.
So we're going to have
to systematically
sweep the ship
with phaser fire.
Every conduit, every corridor.
If he's out there,
we'll find him.
Any questions?
What if the changeling's
not out there?
What if he's one of us?
SISKO:
That's why everyone
will be in teams.
Keep your partner in sight
at all times.
And if we see anyone
without a partner?
Escort them
to the brig.
We don't want
to take any chances.
Let's go.
All right, let's go.
After you.
Don't you trust me?
No, I don't.
I know exactly how you feel.
Follow me.
( sighs )
Don't you ever sweat?
No, I don't.
It's the modified phaser beam.
It's heating
up the air.
Hmm.
You know,
this would be a lot easier
if we knew where he was hiding.
Where would you be
if you were him?
I wouldn't know.
I'm not him.
He is one of your people.
Now, can't you put yourself
in his position?
Try to anticipate
his next move?
I've thought about it,
but the truth is
I don't understand my people
all that well.
That's too bad.
Yes, it is.
For all of us.
( whispering ):
Watch my back.
Over here.
On three.
One...
two...
( groans )
This is Sisko.
The changeling is
in Jefferies tube 7-A
heading to the lower deck.
I'm in pursuit!
The changeling...
he's right over there.
Put your phaser down.
It's me, Kira.
We were on our way
to meet you and we got
separated for a second.
The next thing I know,
he opens fire.
BOLIAN:
You can't fool me.
You're the changeling!
I saw you come out of that hatch
and go around the corner!
I didn't see anyone!
What...
Maybe he morphed
into the ventilation system...
or maybe he didn't.
For all we know,
you may be the changeling.
Keep back!
Both of you, put
your weapons down now!
I can't do that, Captain.
You heard him!
What happened?
How long have
the two of you been apart?
At least a minute.
Then we've got a problem.
Any one of us could be
the changeling.
You, Kira, Eddington,
even me.
Not you.
What do you mean?
You're bleeding.
I cut my hand
when the changeling attacked me.
What are you getting at?
When blood leaves a humanoid
body, it's still blood.
But when any part of me
separates
from my
body...
It reverts back
to a gelatinous state.
Sisko to Bashir.
This is Bashir.
Doctor, meet us in the
Mess Hall immediately.
This shouldn't take long.
Satisfied?
So far.
Who's next?
I'll go.
I'd say the Major is exactly
who she appears to be.
Try not to look
so surprised.
There doesn't seem
to be any point
in obtaining a sample
from the Constable.
I guess that just leaves
the three of us.
Let's get this
over with.
You better come with us.
This is ridiculous.
I'm not the changeling.
If I were,
don't you think
I'd put up a little more
of a fight?
Inside.
You're making
a mistake.
Do as he says!
BASHIR:
Will someone
please get me
out of here!
Bridge to Captain Sisko.
Sisko here.
Sir, we're entering
Tzenkethi space.
Any sign of
Tzenkethi ships?
Sensors aren't picking up
any warp signatures.
We've altered course.
Our new heading is 015 mark 47.
We're headed directly
for the Tzenkethi settlement
on M'kemas III.
How long before we're in weapons
range of the settlement?
12 minutes.
Computer.
This is Captain Benjamin Sisko.
Initiate autodestruct sequence.
Authorization:
Sisko-alpha-one-alpha.
COMPUTER:
Identity confirmed.
Additional authorization
required.
This is First Officer
Kira Nerys.
Autodestruct authorization:
Kira-beta-two-beta.
COMPUTER:
Identity confirmed.
Autodestruct sequence armed.
Set the countdown
for ten minutes from my mark.
Authorization:
Sisko-one-five destruct.
Mark.
COMPUTER:
Sequence initiated.
Autodestruct
in nine minutes, 55 seconds.
Sisko to O'Brien.
O'Brien here.
I could use some good news
right now, Chief.
How about this?
I think I may be able
to shut down
the changeling's force fields
and gain access
to the sabotaged systems.
The only problem is
we may lose
our force fields, too.
COMPUTER:
Autodestruct in seven minutes.
Just tell me
how long it will take.
Well, I guess
it'll have to be
less than seven minutes,
won't it?
That'd be my suggestion.
Sisko out.
EDDINGTON:
Doctor, how's Lieutenant Dax?
Still unconscious.
The changeling gave
her enough sedative
to keep her under
for days.
I've managed
to filter most of it
out of her system,
but she'll be out
for another few hours.
I wish I could do more.
SISKO:
You've done all you can,
Doctor.
Now it's up to Chief O'Brien.
( sighs )
COMPUTER:
Autodestruct in six minutes.
All right,
we're almost there.
Now, look, when we
set this device off,
there's a possibility
we may lose
the protective field
around the warp core.
If that happens, this room's
going to heat up real fast.
So give the warp core
a wide berth
or you'll get a dose
of radiation poisoning
even Bashir can't cure.
Where's the
changeling?
I lost him
in the conduits.
We haven't seen him.
Wait!
It's me,
Odo.
You don't say?
Chief, remember
the last time
we went kayaking
in the holosuite?
You had lamb stew
for lunch.
That's right.
But you forgot
to bring a fork.
Anyone could have gotten
that information.
COMPUTER:
Autodestruct in five minutes.
You'd better
make a decision.
We're running
out of time.
Look, I've more important
things to do
than play
"choose the changeling."
Keep the phaser
on both of them.
KIRA:
The shuttlebay
doors are sealed.
The evacuation pods
are locked down.
We have no way out.
Weapons are fully charged
and ready to fire.
Tactical systems
are programming an attack run
on the Tzenkethi
settlement.
Chief, what are you doing?
COMPUTER:
Autodestruct in four minutes.
You'll see.
Now!
( alarm blaring )
COMPUTER: Warning:
Warp core field breach.
Engine Room will be sealed
in ten seconds.
Evacuate immediately.
Shut down the main power grid!
( screaming )
( grunts )
No!
( groans )
COMPUTER:
Engine room sealed.
( gasps )
Why are you protecting
these solids?
You don't belong
with them.
You belong with us.
Autodestruct in three minutes.
Let go.
Don't you see?
You've lost.
It's too late
for you to help them,
but it's not to late
to help yourself.
Link with me, Odo.
We can escape
together.
( laboriously ):
I... don't...
think... so!
Autodestruct in two minutes.
You've got to regain
control of the ship!
( weakly ):
Odo.
I never wanted to harm you.
( sighs )
O'Brien to Bridge.
Go ahead, Chief.
I've restored control
to the helm.
She's all yours, Captain.
Hard aport, Major.
Take us away from
the settlement.
Computer, end
autodestruct sequence.
Authorization:
Sisko-omega-one-seven abort.
This is Kira Nerys,
First Officer. I concur.
COMPUTER:
Autodestruct sequence aborted.
Phaser banks are powering down.
Take us home, Major.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've returned to the station
without further incident.
However, I'm concerned
about my Chief of Security,
who hasn't said a word
since we left Tzenkethi space.
The real Ambassador Krajensky
was supposed to be
on his way to Risa
for an extended vacation,
but he never arrived.
Starfleet Security
believes he's been kidnapped
or possibly killed.
What about the coup
on the Tzenkethi
homeworld?
It never happened.
Starfleet Command wants
a detailed report
from each of us.
( door opens )
Odo, are you
all right?
I'm fine.
I hope
I'm not interrupting.
Not at all.
Have a seat.
Captain...
there's something
you need to know.
The changeling,
before he... died,
he whispered
something to me.
Go on.
He said...
"You're too late.
We are everywhere."