( beeping )
O'Brien to Sisko.
Go ahead.
We've swept all of Level 17.
No sign of the changeling.
Move down to 18.
We'll meet you there
after we finish checking
the guest quarters.
Watch yourself, Chief.
This changeling knows
the station as well as we do.
He could be anywhere...
or anything.
O'BRIEN:
Aye, Major.
We found him!
He's headed to the Promenade!
Just there.
All right, I want phaser sweeps
of everything on the Promenade.
He's here somewhere.
Let's find him.
On three.
One... two...
Bang. You're dead.
And so is Dr. Bashir.
Computer, elapsed time?
Three hours, 27 minutes.
That's not good enough.
If one of my people were loose
on the station for that long,
there's no telling how much
damage they could do.
Schedule another surprise drill.
If the Dominion tries
to infiltrate the station,
I want to be ready for them.
ODO:
And remind everyone
that next time, they'd
better sweep everything.
A changeling can be
anything-- a post, a pillar,
even a patch of
reflective surfacing.
We get the message,
Constable.
I hope so, Chief.
Just remember
that the Founders
are even better shape-
shifters than I am.
Excuse me.
If you're done
scaring my customers away,
I'd like to open the bar.
Go right ahead.
Thank you.
Constable...
it just occurred to me
that, if I knew in advance
just how long it will take
for them to catch you
during the next drill...
Well, let's just say
you and I could share
a substantial profit.
( groaning )
Think about it.
Performance reviews
will be held tomorrow
starting at 0800 hours
in the Wardroom.
Check your team leaders
for the schedule.
Dismissed.
( sighing )
How about some dinner?
Oh, not tonight.
I have a previous
engagement.
Oh, that's right--
Captain Yates got in
this morning.
Give her my regards.
I will.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Ben.
I hope I'm not too late.
Some things are
worth waiting for.
Oh...
Nice...
I'm glad you like it.
For you.
Isn't that a coincidence?
I have something
for you, too.
Uh...
Oh!
Where did you find
Tholian silk?
The Tholian Ambassador
owed me a favor.
May I?
It's... not silk,
but I-I think you'll like it.
( laughing )
It's from my brother's team.
The Pike City Pioneers.
My brother says if you're
ever on Cestus III,
he'll get you seats
in the dugout.
How far is Cestus III?
Eight weeks, at maximum warp.
To see a real baseball game...
it might be worth the trip.
If you ever decide to go,
I'll take you there myself...
as long as you don't mind
traveling by freighter.
I just might take
you up on that.
Oh!
Did you do this all yourself?
Well, my father always says
the way to a woman's heart
is through her stomach.
So it's my
heart you're after.
I never could keep a secret.
In that case, uh,
maybe you could tell me
what all those maintenance crews
are doing in the docking ring.
Just some retrofitting.
Now you are keeping a secret.
Let's just say... we're
preparing a few surprises
just in case the Dominion
comes through the wormhole.
It seems like everyone's
got the Dominion
on their minds these days.
I hear the Cardassians
have even sealed their borders.
What do you say we forget
about... business for a while?
I'd say that's a good idea.
( beeping )
Dax to Sisko.
Go ahead.
DAX: I think you'd better
get up here.
On my way.
I'll be back as...
soon as I can.
I know you will.
DAX:
Benjamin, take a look at this.
We've got
some unexpected company.
It's just de-cloaked.
Ah, the new Klingon flagship.
The Negh'Var.
There's a General Martok on
board asking to speak with you.
Put him through.
Captain Sisko,
I bring you greetings
from your allies
in the Klingon Empire.
Welcome to Deep Space 9,
General.
Is there something
I can do for you?
It has been a long journey.
My men require shore leave.
Certainly. They can come
aboard any time they like.
Good.
Sowee TAH!
( muted conversations )
Oh, Chief...
I'm beginning to think
there's no limit
to the wonders you can perform.
That's what I like
about you, Julian--
you're easily impressed.
( chuckles )
Thank you, Quark.
Can we get a
little yamok sauce
for these sand peas?
Quark?
Listen.
Do you hear that?
I don't hear a thing.
Exactly. The ambient noise level
in this room
is less than 30 decibels.
On an average day, it's 65.
When there are Klingons in the
room, it can go as high as 85.
So what you're trying
to say is... it's quiet in here.
Too quiet.
Something is terribly wrong.
( whispers ):
Well, like what?
I don't know,
but have you ever met
a quiet Klingon before?
Look how they're watching
the room.
It's like they're
picking out targets.
( clears throat )
Where are you going?
Well, I thought
I'd ask the Klingons
what they're up to.
Don't do that.
Why not?
Because I don't want them
to know we're onto them.
Well, suit yourself.
No, the secret is positioning
the pea correctly on the hand.
But I thought I had that.
What are you two doing?
I'm telling you, the Klingons
are up to something.
Calm down, Quark.
The Klingons are our allies.
They might be
your allies,
but they're not mine.
Relax. If there's something up
with the Klingons,
Captain Sisko will
find out about it.
Yeah, but will he tell me?
So, what brings
you here, General?
A valid question.
But first...
let us be sure
we are all
who we say we are.
You think we're changelings?
What I think doesn't matter.
The blood
will tell.
Hmm...
Now that that's over with...
We have been sent here to fight
alongside our Federation allies
against the Dominion.
I appreciate
your gesture,
but I'm not sure it's necessary.
The Klingon High Council
thinks it is.
Our communications relay
in the Gamma Quadrant
hasn't detected any signs
of Jem'Hadar activity
for quite some time.
They seem to be giving
the wormhole a wide berth.
They will come,
and when they do,
we will be ready for them.
( laughing )
DAX:
Oh, there you are.
We've been looking
all over for you.
Malko here just gave me
the most...
( sighing ):
amazing massage
and I'm sure, if you ask nicely,
he'll do the same for you.
No, thanks.
Why?
Because Malko's not real.
He's a puppet
made out of holographic light
and replicated matter.
Boys...
can you wait outside?
( laughing )
Are you afraid I hurt
their feelings?
Oh, you really
should try to get
into the spirit of things.
People come from all over Trill
to visit the Hoobishan Baths.
If I'm ever on Trill,
I'm sure I'll visit them,
but we're not on Trill,
and this isn't
the Hoobishan Baths.
It's a holosuite,
and none of it is real.
And?
"And"?
I'm sorry. I feel silly.
Good! That's what
a holosuite's for--
to have a good time.
All you have to do is relax
and use your imagination.
I guess I don't have
much of an imagination.
Of course you do.
Everyone does.
Didn't you play make-believe
when you were a child?
Yeah. I used to make
believe the Cardassians
would stop killing the Bajorans
and just go away.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
Oh, no. I'm sorry.
I... I guess I never had
much use for my imagination.
I mean, look at me.
You plan a fun evening for us,
and all I can do is sit here
and worry about Klingons.
You can worry
about the Klingons tomorrow.
From what I hear,
they're not going anywhere.
And as for your underdeveloped
imagination,
I prescribe
a strict regime of exercise
starting immediately.
All right.
I'll give it a try.
That's all I ask.
Come on. Malko couldn't
have gone far.
Fascinating. So both
the cup and the liquid
are merely extensions
of your body.
That is correct.
And if I want to, I can
even drink the liquid,
reabsorb it,
and produce new coffee
in the cup.
This way, I can give
the illusion that I'm sharing
the dining experience.
Very thoughtful.
Tell me, Odo, have you heard
any news from Cardassia lately?
Not since they sealed
their borders.
Well, I have, and frankly,
I don't like what I've heard--
rumors of uprising,
civil disturbance.
It's all very alarming.
I didn't know you still had
friends inside the Empire.
One or two, but I can't even
get through to them now.
That's what worries me.
With the destruction
of the Obsidian Order
and the threat of the Dominion,
these are unsettling times
for Cardassia.
They're unsettling
for everyone...
MALE:
Stop! What are
you doing here?
Let me see that!
But if I hear anything,
I'll let you know.
I'd appreciate that, Constable.
Excuse me for a moment.
KLINGON:
...so far away from
the Firelight Nebula.
So what is it that you
do on this station?
Can I help you?
Lohd Zoss-lee chaw-KU
sohk jaTAL?
Actually, I'm not sure
Constable Odo has a mother.
ODO:
Morn, I believe
Ensign Saunders
was looking for you.
Gentlemen, if you have
business on this Promenade,
I suggest you get on
with it.
I'd listen to him,
if I were you.
I don't take orders
from shape-shifters
or their Cardassian
lapdogs.
I may be a shape-shifter,
but I am also
Chief of Security
of this station,
so either move along
or you'll be continuing
this conversation
from inside
a holding cell.
( growls )
As long as you wear
that Bajoran uniform,
we're allies.
Make sure you never
take it off.
I didn't know
you spoke Klingon.
Oh, you'd be surprised at
the things you can learn
when you're doing
alterations.
Well, let me guess--
you're either lost
or desperately searching
for a good tailor.
Guess again!
( grunts )
I can't believe
you're not pressing charges.
Constable Odo and Captain Sisko
expressed a similar concern.
But really, Doctor,
there was no harm done.
They broke seven
of your transverse ribs
and fractured
your clavicle.
Ah, but I got off
several cutting remarks,
which no doubt did
serious damage to their egos.
Garak, this
isn't funny.
I'm serious, Doctor.
Thanks to your
ministrations,
I am almost
completely healed.
But the damage I did to
them will last a lifetime.
What I can't understand
is their inexplicable
hostility toward me.
Maligning Constable
Odo is one thing--
after all, he's a changeling.
The Klingons don't know
him as well as we do.
But relations between the
Klingon and Cardassian Empires
have never been
anything but amicable.
With the exception
of the Betreka Nebula Incident.
A minor skirmish.
It lasted 18 years.
It was ages ago.
Perhaps they decided
they just didn't like me.
Not like you?
Impossible.
You're right.
( groaning ):
As always, Doctor.
They must have mistaken me
for someone else.
The Klingon ships keep
cloaking and de-cloaking,
so it's impossible
to get an exact count,
but so far, we've been
able to identify
at least 20 different warships
in the vicinity
of the station.
DAX:
Captain, we're receiving
a priority one distress call
from the Freighter Xhosa.
Kasidy's ship?
She left the station
an hour ago.
Put her through.
This is the Freighter Xhosa
to Deep Space 9.
We're under attack by--
Her signal's been jammed.
Get a fix on her location.
Tell the crew on the Defiant
to man their stations.
We'll meet you on the Bridge.
Defiant.
Forward scanners
are detecting the Xhosa
at bearing 017 mark 346.
I'm picking up another ship.
It's got a tractor beam
on the Xhosa.
On screen.
A Klingon ship?
I can't get through to Kasidy.
They're still jamming
her communications.
Hail the Klingon vessel.
This is Commander Kaybok
of the M'Char.
What is it you want?
I want to know
why you stopped that ship.
KAYBOK:
We have orders
to search all vessels attempting
to leave Bajoran space.
Search them for what?
KAYBOK:
For shape-shifters.
Each ship will be scanned,
its cargo searched,
and its crew members
and passengers
subjected to genetic testing.
On whose authority?
On the authority of Gowron
and the Klingon High Council.
The Klingon High Council
has no jurisdiction
over ships in Bajoran space.
KAYBOK: We assumed
you would welcome
our assistance.
Do you have any evidence
that there are changelings
aboard this particular ship?
How can we have evidence
until we conduct our tests?
Commander, Bajoran law strictly
prohibits any unwarranted
search and seizure
of vessels in our territory.
I have my orders.
The Klingon ship has increased
power to its tractor beam.
It looks like they're preparing
to board the Xhosa.
Major, raise shields.
Power up the forward phasers.
See if that gets
their attention.
Shields up.
Forward phasers standing by.
They're still not releasing
the tractor beam.
Fire a warning shot 200 meters
off their starboard bow.
Yes, sir.
( console beeping )
Commander Kaybok would
like to speak with you.
Let's hear what
he has to say.
Captain, this is outrageous!
I agree.
But you leave me no choice.
You're violating Bajoran law.
Now, I will ask you
one last time.
Release that ship immediately.
We are your allies.
Major,
lock phasers
on M'Char's engines.
Prepare to fire on my command.
Phasers ready.
K'trek im stram.
Gowron will hear of this.
I'm receiving a hail
from the Xhosa.
It's Captain Yates.
Put her through.
Captain, I don't know
what you said
to those Klingons,
but it must have been good.
Is everyone all right?
Everyone is fine.
I'm glad to hear it.
We'll keep you on sensors
as long as we can,
but I doubt the Klingons
will give you any more trouble.
I appreciate that, Captain.
I'll see you in about two weeks.
You know where to find me.
According to our
long-range sensors,
the Klingon task force
has withdrawn
to just outside
Bajoran territory.
So now they're
in unclaimed space.
And if they decide
to continue
searching ships...
There's nothing
we can do about it.
Unless they try to stop
a Federation or Bajoran vessel.
Which so far,
they haven't done.
( beeping )
O'BRIEN: Captain, General
Martok is here to see you.
Send him in.
Yes, sir.
Ah, General.
We need to talk.
SOHK-vad.
It's Commander Kaybok's.
Why did he
give it to me?
He's letting you know
Kaybok's dead.
Martok probably had him
executed for disobeying orders.
Which means, our
next confrontation
with the Klingons won't
be resolved so easily.
Any suggestions, old man?
The longer the Klingons
are here,
the worse things
are going to get.
Whatever you decide to do,
you'd better do it soon.
Curzon told me once
that, in the long run,
the only people who can
really handle the Klingons
are Klingons.
Get me Starfleet Command.
O'BRIEN:
Commander Worf.
Chief. It has been
a long time.
Too long.
Welcome aboard.
Just what this station needs...
another Klingon.
Come on.
Lieutenant Commander Worf
reporting for duty, sir.
It's good to have you aboard,
Commander.
Thank you, sir.
At ease, Mr. Worf.
I was sorry to hear
about the Enterprise.
She was a good ship.
Yes, sir.
I understand you've been
on extended leave.
Yes, I have
been visiting
the Klingon monastery on Boreth.
I found my discussions
with the clerics there
to be most enlightening.
Well, I hope you'll forgive me
for pulling you
away from your studies,
but I doubt that this assignment
will take very long.
My leave was almost over, sir.
Do you have any idea
where you'll be stationed next?
I am considering resigning
my commission.
Really?
May I ask why?
I have spent
most of my life among humans.
It has not always been
easy for me.
And since the destruction
of the Enterprise,
it has become
even more difficult.
I am no longer sure
I belong in this uniform.
Mr. Worf, if I told you
we didn't need you here,
I'd be lying,
but if you don't want to take
this assignment, I'd understand.
Thank you, sir,
but until I make my decision,
I intend to do my duty.
I'm glad to hear that.
I assume you've read
my situation report.
Yes, sir.
I can't help but feel
that General Martok
isn't telling the whole truth
about this Klingon task force.
There are too many
unanswered questions.
Then I will find you
some answers.
Good.
If you need any help,
let me know.
Yes, sir.
Commander.
I once thought about resigning
from Starfleet, too.
I know if I had,
I would have regretted it.
Don't make any quick decisions.
I will keep that in mind.
Let me guess--
Klingon bloodwine.
Prune juice, chilled.
( laughing ):
Prune juice?
I-If you say so.
O'BRIEN:
Commander, over here.
Dr. Julian Bashir,
Lieutenant Commander Worf.
Care for a game of darts?
I do not play games.
It's like poker,
but with pointed tips.
All right, think of it
as target practice.
The object is
to throw this dart
and hit that board
over there.
Aim for the dot
in the middle.
( short-circuiting )
KIRA:
Well, you saw how he was acting!
DAX:
I can't believe you did that!
Well, he didn't
leave me any choice.
BASHIR:
Wait, wait, wait.
What did she do?
She knocked
out Lancelot.
He kissed me.
He's supposed
to kiss you.
But I was playing
a married woman.
BASHIR:
Uh, Lieutenant
Commander Worf--
this is Lieutenant
Commander Jadzia Dax
and Major Kira Nerys--
our First Officer.
Nice hat.
I, uh...
I don't usually dress like this.
We were in the holosuite.
So I gathered.
You used to be Curzon Dax.
That's right, and I don't
usually dress like this either.
Curzon's name is
an honored one
among my people.
Louk, a jeek CHIM-ta law.
I suppose so.
KLINGON:
Bartender!
( pounding )
Bloodwine!
And hurry!
Excuse me.
What did you say to him?
It loses something
in the translation.
This bloodwine is cold!
Get me another one!
You are Drex,
son of Martok.
That's right.
I am Worf, son of Mogh.
He's good.
What did I tell you?
( sighing )
( doors chimes )
Enter.
I have come
for my son's d'k tahg.
Give it to me...
or I will take it from you.
Now that you are here...
I have no further need of it.
You robbed my son of his honor
just to get my attention?
You cannot take away
what someone does not have.
You're saying my son
is without honor.
I am saying your son
is a coward and a liar.
And what of his father?
That remains to be seen.
Tell me, what have I done
to earn your disrespect?
The misdeeds your troops have
committed speak for themselves--
attacking a Cardassian tailor,
detaining and searching ships
in neutral space without warning
or provocation...
and you executing
one of your Commanders
because he refused
to fire on a Federation ship.
Whatever we have done
is in the best interest
of the Alpha Quadrant.
You must think me a fool to make
your lies so transparent.
I do not wish to quarrel
with you, Worf.
Nor I with you.
The House of Martok
is an honored one
with a proud tradition,
but I must know
why you are here.
I am here under the authority
of Gowron himself.
I am carrying out his orders.
That should be
all the explanation
a Klingon warrior needs.
You forget,
I am not only a Klingon warrior,
I am a Starfleet officer,
and Starfleet deserves
an explanation.
They will get one soon enough.
Until then, know this:
My mission will determine
the fate
of the Klingon Empire.
Interfere, and you risk
destroying us all.
( door opens )
You shouldn't drop
your left arm like that.
I do not remember
asking you for advice.
I'm just trying to help.
So, how did you
like the program?
I found it adequate,
although I was
surprised to find
a Klingon exercise program
on the holosuite.
It's mine.
You mean Curzon's.
No. I mean it's mine.
Computer, bat'leth.
I thought you might be tired
of fighting holograms.
It would not be
a fair match.
I'll go easy on you.
Very well.
Defend yourself.
I hope you're not holding back
because I'm a woman.
If it makes things any easier,
think of me as a man.
I've been one several times.
Feel better?
( groans )
I take it your conversation
with General Martok
didn't go all that well.
He was not forthcoming,
and he is not the only one.
I tried to contact
Gowron, Emperor Kahless,
even my brother,
who sits on the High Council.
No one will speak with me.
Maybe you're going
about this
the wrong way.
With so many Klingons around,
there must be someone
who owes your family a favor.
♪ Ej IM-ta fey DE-ja i ♪
♪ ejadahk-so-TAS
ghos va Skral byteek ♪
♪ Empa jaj law-moch jaj-pusH ♪
♪ jaj Kayless Molor-migh
hohk-chew koo. ♪
( laughing )
( both yell )
Your father and I
used to sing that song
when you were just a small boy.
Did I ever tell you how your
father saved my family's honor
during our blood feud
with the House of Duras?
Many times.
It is a good story.
Yes, and you tell it well.
Your father was a great warrior.
My family owes him
everything we have.
I wish there was some way
I could repay him.
There is.
Tell me why the task force
is here,
the real reason, not the one
Martok gave the Federation.
The real reason?
I suppose you have
a right to know.
You are a Klingon warrior,
and it would be wrong
to keep you away from battle.
And it's going to be
a glorious battle.
( laughing )
ODO:
It all seems simpler
from up here,
doesn't it?
If you are looking
to start a conversation,
look somewhere else.
I would prefer to be left alone.
That may be, but you
can't stay up here forever.
Sooner or later, you're going to
have to talk to Captain Sisko.
Whatever it is you've found out
about the Klingons,
he should be the
first to know.
You have been spying on me.
As Chief of Security,
it's my duty to observe
the inhabitants of this station.
Since your arrival,
you've transmitted an average
of five messages a day
to the Klingon Homeworld.
None of which has
gotten a response.
Then last night, you met
with a Klingon officer
in your quarters.
Since then, you haven't
sent a single message.
In fact, you've
done nothing
to further your investigation
of the Klingon task force.
None of which
is your business.
The security of this station
is my business.
Your behavior leads
me to conclude
that either you've given up
your investigation,
in which case,
it's my duty to take over,
or... you found something--
something so disturbing
that you're hesitant
to inform Captain Sisko.
I am not interested
in your... conclusions.
Commander?
I just wanted to say
that I understand
what you're going through.
I've also had to choose
between duty
and loyalty to my people.
Yes. I've read
your Starfleet security file.
Frankly, Mr. Worf, I don't care
which choice you make,
but you owe it to Captain Sisko
to let him know
which side you're on,
before it's too late.
Enjoy the view.
Mr. Worf, what can I do for you?
Where is Captain Sisko?
I think he's
in a briefing session with--
I need to talk to him now.
Cardassia?
Why would the Klingons
want to invade Cardassia?
According to my source,
there has been an uprising
on the Cardassian homeworld.
The Central Command
has been overthrown
and power transferred
to civilian authorities.
Even if your source is correct,
what does that have to do
with the Klingons?
Gowron and the High
Council believe the coup
was engineered
by the Dominion.
Do they have any proof?
None that I know of,
but they are convinced
that civilians could
not have overthrown
the Central Command
without help.
So, by attacking Cardassia,
they think they're protecting
the Alpha Quadrant
from the Dominion.
Sisko to Dax.
Contact General Martok.
Tell him I need
to meet with him immediately.
DAX: Yes, sir.
Hmm.
( sighing )
Mr. Worf, I know this hasn't
been an easy assignment for you.
No, it has not.
But I knew this day
would come again
when I'd be forced
to choose
between the Federation
and the Klingon Empire.
Maybe you don't have
to make that choice just yet.
I don't think there's any need
for you to be there
when I meet with Martok.
I would prefer to be there.
I cannot avoid responsibility
for what I have done today.
I must compliment you on your
intelligence network, Captain.
One day, you must tell me
how you learned of our plans.
General...!
How I got the information
isn't important.
I think it is,
and so will Gowron.
General, I want you to
call off this attack.
And what do you propose
we do instead?
Stand by and allow the Dominion
to take over the Alpha Quadrant?
You have no proof that there are
any Founders on Cardassia.
The change in government
is all the proof we need.
And what if you are wrong?
That would be unfortunate...
for the Cardassians.
General, the Federation Council
has made it clear to me
that they cannot support
your plans to attack Cardassia.
Are you saying the Federation
will sit back and do nothing
while Klingon soldiers
give their lives
to protect the Alpha Quadrant?
WORF:
Starfleet will
not participate
in an unprovoked invasion.
Then the victory
will be ours alone!
General, I would advise you
to reconsider.
The Federation Council
has informed Gowron
that if the attack goes forward,
it will jeopardize our treaty
with the
Klingon Empire.
Believe me, Captain, we have no
wish to antagonize your people.
Then call off the attack.
I will consult with Gowron.
You will have his decision
within the hour.
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
DAX:
Captain, I think
you better take a look at this.
SISKO:
Report.
DAX: As soon
as General Martok
beamed back
to his ship,
he sent a message
to the Klingon fleet.
It was just one word-- "In'Cha."
"Begin."
O'BRIEN:
I'm picking up
a huge distortion wave
in subspace.
The Klingon ships
are going to warp.
Can you plot their course?
Judging from the vector
on the subspace disturbance,
I'd say their heading is...
mark 032.
Straight
to the Cardassian Empire.
The Federation Council
has been trying
to contact Gowron.
So far they've had no response.
So until they've had a chance
to speak with him,
we've been ordered
not to get involved.
KIRA:
The Bajoran government
has agreed
to abide by the decisions
of the Federation Council.
So that means we're not going
to warn the Cardassians?
DAX:
The Klingons are
still our allies.
If we warn the Cardassians,
we'd be betraying them.
Besides, what if the
Klingons are right?
What if the Dominion
has taken over the
Cardassian government?
If my people wanted to seize
control of Cardassia,
that is how they would do it.
The coup could have happened
just as easily
without the Founders.
The Cardassian
dissident movement
has been gaining
strength for years.
With the Obsidian Order
out of the way,
they might have
finally succeeded.
WORF:
The issue is not
if there are any Founders
on Cardassia.
There are many Klingons
who say we have been
at peace too long,
that the Empire must expand
in order to survive.
Fear of the Dominion
has given my people an excuse
to do what they were born
to do--
to fight and to conquer.
If they're so eager to fight,
who's to say they'll stop
with the Cardassians?
Next target could be anyone,
even the Federation.
DAX:
If I were you,
I'd be more worried about Bajor.
Think about it.
What good would it do
the Klingons to defeat
Cardassia if they don't
control the wormhole?
Agreed.
If my people return to the
old ways, no one will be safe.
Then we'll have to make sure
that doesn't happen.
O'BRIEN:
But how?
The way I see it,
we only have two choices.
Both of them bad.
If we stand by and do nothing,
we run the risk of being
the Klingons' next target.
But if we disobey Starfleet
orders and warn the Cardassians,
we may end up starting
a war with the Klingons.
Which means...
we need a third option.
Trust me, you
won't regret this.
When it comes
to keeping warm,
nothing beats
Vitarian wool undergarments.
And in case you change your mind
about those earmuffs,
I'll keep them
on hold for you.
SISKO:
Mr. Garak, I'd like to see you
in the Wardroom immediately.
Bring your tailor's kit.
All together,
we're talking
about well over
a hundred ships
just in the first wave.
Excuse me.
I hope I'm not
interrupting.
I'd like to be measured
for a new suit.
Now?
Right now.
But, Captain, I do have
your measurements.
Take them again.
You were saying, Commander?
I was saying that between
ground forces and warships,
the Klingons
have committed
almost a third of their
military to this invasion.
How long before they reach
their target?
According to our estimates,
the task force
should enter
Cardassian space
within the hour.
SISKO:
Don't forget
the waist.
I think I've lost
a little weight.
Well, thank you, Captain.
I believe
I have everything I need.
The Klingons?
Why would the Klingons
invade us?
According to my sources, the
Klingon High Council believes
that Cardassia has been
taken over by the Founders.
That's ridiculous.
Is it?
Garak, you have got
to talk to Sisko.
Tell him he has to find some way
to stop the Klingons.
Cardassia has enough
problems right now.
Having trouble
keeping the civilians in line?
How do you know about that?
I'm afraid that since the fall
of the Obsidian Order,
Cardassian security
isn't what it used to be.
Yes.
Shame about the Order.
I suppose there won't be
much demand
for your services anymore.
Looks like you'll be
hemming women's dresses
for the rest of your life.
We can stand here all day
reminding ourselves
just how much
we hate each other,
but you don't have the time.
The Klingon fleet will reach
Cardassian territory
in less than one hour.
I suggest you prepare for them.
KIRA:
Based on Klingon
transmissions,
we've intercepted,
the outlying Cardassian colonies
were overrun almost immediately.
But now that the Cardassian
fleet has mobilized,
the Klingons are meeting
stronger resistance.
You'd almost think
somebody warned
the Cardassians
they were coming.
Hopefully, it'll make
the Klingons
think twice
about what they're doing.
Unlikely, Major.
Now that the battle has begun,
Martok and his troops
will settle for nothing
less than victory.
( sighs )
O'BRIEN:
Well...
what did the Federation
Council say?
They've decided to condemn
the Klingon invasion.
In response...
Gowron has expelled
all Federation citizens
from the Klingon Empire
and recalled
his Ambassadors
from the Federation.
You're saying he cut off
diplomatic relations?
He's done more than that.
The Klingons have withdrawn
from the Khitomer Accords.
The peace treaty
between the Federation
and the Klingon Empire
has ended.
O'BRIEN:
Captain.
You're never going
to believe this.
A Klingon ship
just de-cloaked
off Upper Pylon 3
and is requesting
permission to dock.
They claim they have
Chancellor Gowron on board,
and he is demanding
to speak with Mr. Worf...
personally.
Chancellor Gowron.
You wished
to speak with me?
Worf.
Worf!
It is good to see you.
I always said that uniform
would get you into
trouble one day.
It seems you were right,
but I do not apologize for my--
Yes, yes, I know.
You did what you thought
was right.
And even though you may
have made some enemies,
I assure you, ha,
I am not one of them.
I am glad.
Your friendship
means much to me.
And yours to me.
It has been too long since
you last fought at my side.
Now the time
has come again.
We will do great deeds
in the coming days.
Deeds worthy of song!
You want me to go
to Cardassia with you?
What better way
to redeem yourself
in the eyes of your people?
Come with me, Worf.
Glory awaits you
on Cardassia.
Worf, why do you stand there
like a mute d'blok?
I have offered you
a chance for glory.
All you have to do is take it.
If there's any glory
to be won, Gowron,
it'll have to be yours alone.
I cannot come with you.
Of course you can.
It is where you belong.
I cannot abandon my post.
You no longer have a post.
You have no place
on that station
and no business
wearing that uniform.
I have sworn
an oath of allegiance.
To the Federation!
You would
have me
break my word?
Your word?
What good is your word
when you give it to people
who care nothing for honor?
Who refuse to lift a finger
while Klingon warriors
shed blood for their protection?
I tell you,
they are without honor,
and you do not
owe them anything!
It is not what I owe them
that matters.
It is what I owe myself.
Worf, son of Mogh,
does not break his word.
And what of your debt to me?
Are you saying
you owe me nothing?
I gave you back your name,
restored your house,
gave your family a seat
on the High Council,
and this is how you repay me?
It is true.
I owe you a great debt.
I would give up my life for you.
But invading Cardassia is wrong,
and I cannot support it.
Worf... I have
always considered you
a friend and an ally.
And because you
are my friend,
I am giving you this one
last chance to redeem yourself.
Come with me.
I cannot.
Think about what
you are doing.
If you turn your
back on me now,
for as long as I live,
you will not be welcome
anywhere in the
Klingon Empire.
Your family
will be removed
from the High Council,
your lands seized,
and your House
stripped of its titles!
You will have nothing!
Except my honor.
So be it.
( loud conversation
and laughter )
MALE:
Dabo!
ALL:
You look like you could
use some company.
Chief, do you remember the time
we rescued Captain Picard
from the Borg?
How could I forget?
It was touch and go there
for a while.
There were a couple of moments
when I thought we were all going
to wind up being "assimilated."
Well, I never doubted
the outcome.
We were like... warriors
from the ancient sagas.
There was nothing
we could not do.
Except keep the holodecks
working right.
I... have decided
to resign from Starfleet.
Resign?
What are you talking about?
I have made up my mind.
It is for the best.
Look, I-I know how much
you miss the Enterprise,
but I'm sure they'll be
building a new one soon.
It will not be the same.
The Enterprise I knew is gone.
Now those were good years.
But now it is time
for me to move on.
And do what?
I do not know.
I thought I would be returning
to Boreth,
but now that is impossible.
I have made an enemy of Gowron
and every other Klingon
in the Empire.
All the more reason
to stay in Starfleet.
This uniform will only serve
to remind me
of how I have disgraced myself
in the eyes of my people.
I suppose I could get a berth
on a Nyberrite Alliance cruiser.
They are always eager to hire
experienced officers.
The Nyberrite Alliance?
That's a long way.
And what about your son?
Alexander is much happier
living with his grandparents
on Earth
than he ever was
staying with me.
And one thing is certain...
the sooner I leave here,
the better.
My continued presence
on Deep Space 9
would only be a liability
to Captain Sisko
in his dealings
with the Klingons.
Do you hear
that, Chief?
72 decibels.
Music to my ears.
I think I
liked it better
when it was quiet.
You want quiet,
go to the Replimat.
This is Quark's
the way Quark's should be,
the way it was meant to be.
Am I glad
we finally got rid
of all those Klingons.
Uh... present company
excepted, of course.
I got to hand it
to you, Quark.
You really know
how to make
your customers
feel welcome.
What do I care?
All he ever drinks
is prune juice.
I'm sorry, Mr. Worf,
but I can't accept your
resignation at this time.
I do not understand.
What further use
could I be here?
I'm not sure yet.
But as long
as the fighting continues
between the Klingons
and the Cardassians,
I need you here on the station.
If you think that is wise.
( chuckles )
I don't know
if it's wise or not.
But I do know
that you're a good officer,
and right now, I need
every good officer I can get.
Captain, we just got word
from Bajoran Intelligence.
The Klingons have broken through
the Cardassian fleet.
How long before they reach
Cardassia Prime?
52 hours.
If the Klingon Empire has
reverted to the old practices,
they will occupy
the Cardassian homeworld,
execute all
government officials,
and install
an Imperial Overseer
to put down
any further resistance.
I think it's about time we had
a talk with the Cardassians.
Captain, I'm a little busy
at the moment,
so whatever you have to say,
please make it brief.
Dukat?
I was trying to reach someone
in the civilian government.
And you have succeeded.
You are speaking to the new
Chief Military Advisor
to the Detapa Council.
Does this mean
you've turned
your back on Central Command?
It means that as a loyal officer
of the Cardassian military,
I am pledged to serve
the legitimate ruling body
of the Empire,
whoever that may be.
In other words, you saw
which way the wind was blowing
and switched sides.
It seemed like a good idea
at the time.
Dukat, you have got to get
those council members to safety
before the Klingons
reach Cardassia Prime.
I am open to suggestions,
Captain.
If you can get a ship
and meet me at
these coordinates,
I'll do what I can
to escort you
out of the war zone.
That is a very generous offer.
I must say I am touched.
By saving the members
of the Detapa Council
you will be saving some very...
Forget the
speech, Dukat.
Just meet me
at the rendezvous point.
And if the Klingons
try to stop us?
Then I'll be there
to reason with them.
I doubt the Klingons
will fire on a Federation ship.
I'm not sure I share
your optimism.
But, then, I don't have
much choice, do I?
We'll meet you there.
WORF:
Sir...
if the Klingons are right--
if the Cardassian government
has been taken over
by the Founders--
Then we'll be helping
them to escape.
That's the chance
we'll have to take.
I know you want to be
out of that uniform,
but right now,
I need you with me.
I understand.
Make sure the Chief
double-checks
all our new systems.
We may need them.
I'll tell him,
but knowing the Chief,
he's probably
doing it already.
Keep the station
on Yellow Alert.
And just to be
on the safe side,
I'd recommend that you send
some of the civilian population
down to Bajor.
I was planning to.
I wish I was
going with you.
So do I.
But I need you here.
Ben!
I'm, uh... glad
I caught you
before you left.
So am I.
When'd you get back?
Uh, less than an hour ago.
Jake told me you were
about to go off on...
some kind of mission.
The Defiant leaves
in a few minutes.
And you can't tell me
about it.
I'll be back in
four or five days.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Phew!
I guess our timing
hasn't been too good.
No.
No, it's been terrible.
I'm not even sure
when I'll be back.
Make it soon.
Don't get killed.
I'll do my best.
Activate the cloaking device.
Cloaking device
is functioning
within normal
parameters.
Set a course
for the rendezvous point.
Maximum warp.
Course laid in.
Engage.
Mr. Worf,
keep an eye out
for Klingon ships
cloaked
or otherwise.
Aye, sir.
Is something wrong,
Mr. Worf?
No, sir.
Yes, sir.
It is just...
I have never been
on a Federation starship
that had a cloaking device.
It is... a little strange.
You'll get used to it.
Sir, I hate to bring this up,
but our agreement
with the Romulans
expressly prohibits use
of the cloaking device
in the Alpha Quadrant.
You're right, it does.
But there are hundreds
of Klingon ships
between us and Dukat,
and I intend to make
that rendezvous in one piece.
Well, I won't tell the Romulans
if you don't.
I never thought I'd say this,
but right now...
I'm glad the Dominion's around.
Otherwise, we never would have
started these upgrades,
let alone have them
almost finished by now.
Well, there's something to be
said for incentive.
Uh-huh.
I just hope everything
works okay.
You're saying
you're not sure?
The way I see it
there are two
possibilities.
Either everything
will be fine, or...
Or?
Or we'll end up blowing
the station to pieces.
Oh.
Well, let's hope
we don't have to find out.
( chuckling )
WORF:
Captain...
I am detecting some debris.
Bearing 025 mark 319.
Commander, drop us
to one-quarter impulse.
Aye, Captain.
It appears to be the wreckage
of a number
of Cardassian vessels.
On screen.
BASHIR:
Are there any signs
of survivors?
I suppose it's possible.
But there's no way to know
without de-cloaking
and using our primary
sensor array.
Sir, I strongly recommend
against that.
It is likely there are
cloaked Klingon warships
in the vicinity lying in wait.
Well, that doesn't sound
very honorable to me.
In war, there is nothing
more honorable than victory.
Commander, keep us
at one-quarter impulse...
until we've cleared
the wreckage.
Then take us to warp.
But, sir...
if there are survivors...
I'm sorry, Doctor,
we can't risk it.
We have to reach Dukat.
And double-check the
secondary power grid.
It's still
not performing
as well as
it should.
Yes, sir.
What's our status?
We're approaching
the rendezvous point.
Captain, I am detecting
weapons fire ahead.
It appears to be three
Klingon birds-of-prey
attacking a Cardassian vessel.
The vessel is badly damaged.
Captain, I'm picking up
a distress signal
from Dukat, audio only.
Put it through.
(staticky ):
This is Gul Dukat
of the Cruiser Prakesh.
We're under heavy fire.
Our shields are failing.
I don't know how much longer
we can hold out.
Send reinforcements immediately.
I repeat, this is--
We're in visual range.
On screen.
Maximum magnification.
Two decades of peace
with the Klingons,
and it all comes down to this.
WORF:
Orders, Captain.
DAX:
Benjamin...
Dukat's ship isn't going
to last much longer.
Arm quantum torpedoes...
drop the cloak,
and raise shields.
We're going in.
Red Alert.
Doctor.
Commander Worf, transmit
a priority one signal
to the Klingon ship.
Tell them to break off
their attack
and stand down immediately.
Message sent.
Captain, I find it
highly unlikely
that the Klingons
will heed your...
We've been fired upon
by the lead bird-of-prey.
Shields are holding.
I see your point, Mr. Worf.
Let's show them
what they're up against.
Attack pattern omega.
Target their engines.
( console beeping )
Incoming message from
the Cardassian ship.
Put it through.
DUKAT: I must
compliment you, Captain.
You're nearly Cardassian
in your punctuality.
Fire phasers!
Dukat, power up your engines
and prepare to follow us
back to DS9.
An excellent suggestion,,
Captain,
assuming
we had any engines left.
What's your status?
Our engines are gone,
our shields are down,
and we have no weapons
to speak of.
Prepare to evacuate.
We'll start to beam you over
as soon as possible.
You'd have
to drop your shields
to use your transporters.
Let me worry about that.
Sisko out.
WORF:
Sir, restricting our fire
to their engines has not
proven effective.
Very well.
Target at your discretion.
Aye, aye, sir.
Dukat's ship is under fire.
I don't know how much longer
they can hold out.
Another Klingon ship
has just de-cloaked.
It is a Vor'cha-class
attack cruiser.
Sisko to Transporter Bay.
Stand by to beam aboard
survivors.
Sisko to Bashir.
Prepare to receive casualties.
And, Doctor, have Security
standing by.
I want our guests
to undergo blood screenings.
BASHIR: Understood.
Blood screenings?
Just in case Martok was right.
Benjamin, it's going to take
at least two minutes
to evacuate Dukat's ship.
Even with the Defiant's
new armor, I don't think
we can last that long
with our
shields down.
WORF:
Sir.
I have a suggestion.
You were right, Mr. Worf.
The modulated tractor
beam's deflecting
some of the Klingon's
disrupter fire.
Disrupter's effectiveness
at 50 percent.
Well done, Mr. Worf.
Lower shields.
Sisko to Transporter Bay.
Begin emergency transports.
Transports underway.
The ablative armor is holding.
Klingon ships are closing.
Armor on the port side
is losing integrity.
Transporter Bay,
what's our status?
Captain, this is Dukat.
Almost half the council members
are still aboard my ship.
We need at least another minute.
Looks like we're going
to find out
just how much of a pounding
this ship can take.
The Klingons have closed
to point-blank range.
DAX:
Ablative armor
has failed.
We've got plasma leaks
on decks 2, 3 and 5.
And we've lost our
aft torpedo launchers.
Dukat to Sisko.
Go ahead.
The council members are aboard.
Raise shields.
Activate the cloak.
WORF:
Shields up.
I'm not getting any response
from the cloaking device.
It's not working.
Well, that should make
the trip home
a little more interesting.
Set a course for DS9,
maximum warp.
Thank you, Doctor,
but if you don't mind,
I would like to go
to the Bridge now.
This will only take a minute.
Your arm, please.
What is the meaning
of this?
Just a simple
blood screening.
I assure you, Doctor,
I am not a changeling.
Then you have nothing
to worry about.
I find this whole
procedure offensive.
And I find you offensive.
Now hold up your arm,
or I'll have a Security
Officer do it for you.
Captain, would
you kindly inform
this security guard
that he does not have
to monitor my every move.
It makes me
feel unwelcome.
DAX:
Looks like
I won, Benjamin.
You owe me dinner.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Captain Sisko bet me that you
would thank him for the rescue
before you started
complaining.
I lost.
Captain, are you aware
there's a Klingon
on your Bridge?
He's not the Klingon you
should be worried about.
Switch to aft view,
maximum magnification.
Hmm.
I'd suggest you cloak
immediately.
We lost our cloaking device
rescuing you.
Might I trouble you
for a glass of kanar?
Help yourself.
It's on the house.
Well, how uncharacteristically
generous of you.
I'm in an
uncharacteristic mood.
Besides, I've got
80 cases of this stuff
sitting in my stockroom.
And the way things
are going,
I'll never unload
another bottle
unless it's to you.
How thoughtless of me
not to consider the effect
the destruction of my homeworld
would have on your business.
These must be
trying times for you.
Be brave.
I should have listened
to my cousin Gaila.
He said to me, "Quark, I got
one word for you... weapons."
No one ever went broke
selling weapons.
But did I take
his advice?
No.
And why not?
Because I'm a people person.
I like interacting
with my customers
like you and I are doing
right now.
Talking to each other,
getting to know
one another.
I can see the attraction
for you.
But when you're dealing
in weapons,
buyers aren't interested
in casual conversation.
They just want
their merchandise,
no questions asked.
So impersonal.
Your charms would be wasted.
Exactly.
So now, Gaila owns his own moon,
and I'm staring into the abyss.
And the worst part of it is,
my only hope for salvation
is the Federation.
I know precisely how you feel.
I want you to try
something for me.
Take sip of this.
What is it?
A human drink.
It's called root beer.
I don't know.
Come on.
Aren't you just
a little bit curious?
( sighs )
What do you think?
It's vile.
I know.
It's so bubbly and cloying
and happy.
Just like the Federation.
But you know
what's really frightening?
If you drink enough of it,
you begin to like it.
It's insidious.
Just like the Federation.
Do you think
they'll be able to save us?
I hope so.
Any luck?
Not yet.
( console beeps )
Hold on.
I'm picking up something
on long-range scanners.
It's the Defiant.
They made it.
Yeah, but they've got
two Klingon ships
on their tail.
The Captain's hailing us.
On screen.
Chief, our ETA
is in five minutes.
Are the new systems on line?
Yes, sir.
I think
we're going to need them.
I wish we could have
tested them first.
No time like the present.
Raise shields.
Red Alert.
( alarm blaring )
Now what?!
Well, I can't be
sure, of course,
but my guess
would be Klingons.
The Klingons?
First, it was the Cardassians,
then it was the Dominion,
now it's the Klingons!
How's a Ferengi supposed
to make an honest living
in a place like this?
Drop out of warp.
Reverse thrusters
at maximum.
Prepare for docking.
DAX:
Aye, sir.
Well, it looks
like the Klingons
chased us all this way
for nothing.
That remains to be seen.
Klingons do not give up easily.
Two ships against a station?
I don't think they'd risk it.
It may not be much of a risk.
Why do you say that?
They've got friends.
Status report, Major.
I'm detecting
several dozen Klingon ships
including the Negh'Var.
They're in
an attack formation.
While you were gone,
we spoke to
Starfleet Command.
They sent a
relief force
under Admiral Hastur.
When will they get here?
Not soon enough.
DAX: The Klingon ships
have raised their shields
and charged
their weapons.
What are your
orders, Captain?
Battle stations.
The thing to remember is
that the Klingons prefer to use
their knives and bat'leths
in close combat.
So if we get boarded, you can
expect severe lacerations,
broken bones,
and blunt force traumas.
All I can say is keep calm,
remember your training...
and do the best that you can.
Report to your posts.
Doctor.
Constable, what can I
do for you?
I just wanted you
to know I'll be assigning
a security unit
to the Infirmary
for your protection.
Well, thank you,
but I'd rather you didn't.
I'm going to have
wounded people in here.
The last thing I need
is a team of deputies
having a fire fight
in my doorway.
I understand.
Just do me a favor.
Don't count on that blue uniform
to protect you.
In the heat of battle,
Klingons aren't very choosy
about their targets.
Doctor or no doctor,
you might end up
having to defend yourself.
Well, hopefully,
it won't come to that.
But if it does,
I promise you I'll be ready.
That's all I ask.
And while we're
on the subject, Constable,
I'm sure there's
more than one Klingon
who thinks that slaying
a changeling
would be worthy
of a song or two.
Doctor, if a Klingon
were to kill me,
I'd expect nothing less than
an entire opera on the subject.
Maybe.
I just don't want
to have to listen to it.
Watch your back.
Come on, Quark,
move it along.
You should be
in the emergency
shelter by now.
I'm not going
to any emergency shelter.
This is my bar,
and I'm going to defend it.
Really? And how do
you plan to do that?
With this.
You're going to hit
them with a box?
No. This is
my disrupter pistol.
The one I used to carry
in the old days
when I was serving
on that Ferengi freighter.
I thought you were
the ship's cook.
That's right.
And every member of that crew
thought he was a food critic.
If the Klingons try
to get through these doors,
I'll be ready for them.
"Dear Quark,
"I used parts of your disrupter
to fix the replicators.
Will return them soon. Rom."
I will kill him.
With what?
That's close enough, Garak.
I wanted to make sure that
the council members were safe.
Hoping, no doubt,
that your concern
would curry
some political favor?
Oh, and I take it
your concern is motivated
strictly by patriotism.
Oh, the council members
are well aware of my patriotism.
And the sacrifices I was willing
to make in order to save them.
Now, why don't you go back
to your little tailor shop
and sew something?
Because if the Klingons
do invade this station,
you may just need... my help.
Who would
have thought
that the two of us
would be fighting
side by side.
Just remember
when you fire that thing,
you're aiming it
at a Klingon.
I'll try to keep
that in mind.
( console beeps )
We're receiving a transmission
from General Martok.
Put him through.
Captain, I demand you surrender
the Cardassian council members
to us immediately.
They're not Founders, Martok.
We tested them.
You were wrong.
It is of no consequence.
All that matters is
the Alpha Quadrant will be safer
with the Klingon Empire
in control of Cardassia.
Now, surrender
the council members,
or we will have no choice
but to take them by force.
And risk an all-out war
with the Federation?
If a war starts here,
the blame will be yours.
I doubt very much
history will agree.
History is written
by the victors.
Consider what you're
doing, Captain.
The lives of everyone on
your station are at risk.
I am aware of that.
But maybe you're not aware
of what you're risking.
We've had a year
to prepare this station
for a Dominion attack,
and we're more than ready.
( chuckles )
You're like a toothless
old Grishnar cat,
trying to frighten us
with your roar.
I can assure you
this old cat may not be
as toothless as you think.
Right now, I've got
5,000 photon torpedoes
armed and ready to launch.
If you don't believe me,
feel free to scan the station.
It is a trick.
An illusion created
by thoron fields
and duranium shadows.
It's no illusion.
We shall see.
CHEGH-chew jaj-VAM jaj-KAK!
He said,
"Today is a good day to die."
Target the lead ships.
Ready even-numbered
photon launchers.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Fire on my mark.
Fire!
Ready odd-numbered launchers.
They're still closing.
Ready phasers.
Standing by.
Fire!
Eight Klingon ships destroyed.
Several heavily damaged.
Contact Gowron.
Maybe we can put an end to this
before it gets any further.
They're not responding.
They have given you
your answer, Captain.
Weapons stations, fire at will.
A TLING-on kaogh.
Zo a TLING-on HegH-lah.
YoD-wee KAW.
TIG-mang-Rup.
jee-YAJ.
DuJ-va, YoD-wee KAW!
( screams )
They've disabled
two of our shield generators.
( groans )
( yells )
( screams )
( groans )
Thank you, Doctor.
Any time.
I find this
hand-to-hand combat
really quite
distasteful.
DUKAT:
I suppose you prefer
the simplicity
of an interrogation chamber.
You have to admit,
it's much more civilized.
( coughing )
Mr. O'Brien?
Yeah.
Get those shields
back on line.
Major?
I'll be okay.
It's not as bad as it looks.
Sisko to Odo.
Odo here.
Status report.
ODO:
We have Klingon troops
on the Promenade,
the Habitat Ring,
and Lower Pylon Three.
They seem to be
contained for now,
but I can't guarantee
it'll stay that way.
Keep me informed.
There is another wave
of Klingon ships coming in.
I've got the shields back up,
but I don't know
how long they'll hold.
I'm reading a cluster
of warp signatures approaching,
bearing 187 mark 025.
It's Starfleet, Benjamin.
Six starships led
by the Venture.
They'll be here
in 15 minutes.
Contact the Negh'Var again.
Maybe now Gowron will be
in the mood to talk.
DAX:
I've got him.
GOWRON:
Captain, your shields
have been weakened,
your station boarded,
and more Klingon ships
are on their way.
Surrender while you can.
I don't think so.
My shields are holding.
Your boarding parties
are contained.
And my reinforcements
are closer than yours.
You're facing a war
on two fronts.
Is that what you really want?
The Empire is not strong enough
to fight the Federation
and the Cardassians.
End this now, Gowron,
before you lead the Empire
to its worst defeat in history.
We will not surrender!
This is exactly
what the Founders want.
Klingon against Cardassian.
Federation against Klingon.
The more we fight each other,
the weaker we'll get,
and the less chance we have
against the Dominion.
Consider what you do here,
Gowron.
Kahless himself said,
"Destroying an Empire
to win a war is no victory."
"And ending a battle to save
an Empire is no defeat."
We can still win!
Not before those Starships
get here.
Now, what do you want me
to tell them?
To stand down,
or to come in firing?
It is we
who shall stand down.
Ach, Gowron, yay chol!
Enough.
Cease fire.
Order our ships
in Cardassian territory
to halt their advance.
I do not intend to hand victory
to the Dominion.
But let your people know
the Klingon Empire will remember
what has happened here.
You have sided against us
in battle,
and this, we do not forgive...
or forget.
The Klingon ships
have powered down their weapons.
It's over.
For now.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 49011.4.
Gowron has returned
to the Klingon Homeworld,
and his task force has
withdrawn from Bajoran space.
I don't know if I can
fully express the pride I felt
at seeing how well
Deep Space 9 and its crew
weathered this latest crisis.
Though the station
suffered heavy damage
during the Klingon attack,
repairs are
well ahead of schedule
and life on the station is
beginning to return to normal,
leaving me with one final piece
of unfinished business.
( door chimes )
Enter.
I brought your discharge papers.
I thought you might want
to take a look at them
before I send them off
to Starfleet.
Thank you, sir.
I understand you're headed
for the Nyberrite Alliance.
Yes, I leave
this afternoon.
For me, it was a job on Earth,
directing construction
of orbital habitats.
Why did you change your mind?
I finally realized
that it wasn't Starfleet
I wanted to get away from.
I was trying to escape the pain
I felt after my wife's death.
I thought I could take
the uniform,
wrap it around that pain,
and toss them both away.
But it doesn't work like that.
Running may help,
for a little while,
but sooner or later the pain
catches up with you,
and the only way
to get rid of it
is to stand your ground
and face it.
But wearing that uniform
must remind you
of what you have lost.
Sometimes...
but it also reminds me
of what I've gained
and who I am.
Oh, I can throw away
the uniform,
resign my commission,
run all the way
to the Nyberrite
Alliance...
but it really wouldn't matter.
A Starfleet Officer--
that's what I am,
and that's what I'll always be.
And you think that is true
of me as well.
What's important, Mr. Worf,
is what you think.
I think Starfleet has been
my home for many years.
Perhaps it still is.
There are starships out there
that are in need
of good officers.
In fact, the Captain of
the Venture is a friend of mine.
If you'd like,
I can talk to him,
see if he has an opening
for a Lieutenant Commander.
Perhaps that
will not be necessary.
Lieutenant Commander Worf
reporting
for duty, sir.
Well, you all know our new
Strategic Operations Officer.
Commander.
Glad you're here.
Thank you.
Congratulations.
Assume your post,
Mr. Worf.
Yes, sir.
You look good in red.
It feels good.
But I have a lot to
learn about command.
Well, you couldn't ask
for a better teacher.
Now that everyone is here,
I wanted you to know
I've spoken with Dukat
and several members
of the Detapa Council.
They've returned to Cardassia
Prime without incident
and wanted me to convey to you
their personal thanks.
( sighs )
Who'd have thought I'd help
save the Cardassian government?
ODO:
Don't worry.
I'm sure Gul Dukat
will take all the credit.
Poor Garak-- Dukat's a hero,
and Garak's still stuck in his
tailor shop hemming trousers.
Captain, I'm receiving
a priority one message
from Starfleet
Intelligence.
The Klingons are refusing
to give up
several
of the Cardassian colonies
they seized during the invasion.
They're fortifying
their positions
and deploying
orbital defense systems.
Looks like the Klingons
are here to stay.
Maybe they are...
but so are we.