Worf to Major Kira.
This is Kira.
Major, you have an incoming
transmission from a...
Razka Karn.
He claims to be an old friend.
Put him through.
Razka... it's been awhile.
How's business?
Oh, let's just say,
I miss the old days on Bajor.
Smuggling might not have been
the safest line of work
but it was a lot more exciting
than selling scrap metal.
What's on your mind, Razka?
I picked up a lead
on the Ravinok.
Like the last time?
Last time, it was just a rumor.
This time I've got evidence...
a fragment of metal.
Looks like it's part
of the forward sensor array.
Can you bring it
to Deep Space 9 for analysis?
Sorry, I'm afraid I can't leave
the Badlands right now.
Important business.
You understand.
Tholians are after you again.
Let's just say it would be
better if you came to me.
It's been six years.
Even if you have found
a piece of the Ravinok
it doesn't mean
there are any survivors.
There's only one way
for you to find out.
I'll be waiting.
And item number 17,
Trelos Vren was arrested
on the Promenade outside
of the Klingon restaurant.
He's being held on four
counts of petty theft.
Trelos Vren... where have I
heard that name before?
We arrested him once
for attempting to break
into the Assay Office.
And now he's taken up
pick-pocketing?
Mmm... without much success.
Still, I suppose you
should admire him
for his persistence.
That was a joke.
I'm sorry, Odo.
I may have a lead
on the Ravinok.
I know what you're going to say.
It's been six years since
the Ravinok disappeared.
Odds are,
everyone on board is dead.
That all may be true
but that is not
what I was going to say.
I was going to say "good luck."
Good luck?
You had a friend aboard
the Ravinok, correct?
Lorit Akrem.
Which means it doesn't matter
if I think
there are any survivors
of even if you think
there are any survivors.
You're going to go
looking for that ship
and all I can say
is "good luck."
And I hope you find them.
Come in.
Captain.
You here to see me off?
I'm afraid not.
I'd like for you
to postpone your trip
for at least a day or two.
What's wrong?
Somehow the Cardassian
government
got wind of your plan
to search for the Ravinok.
They've asked permission
to send someone with you.
And you said yes?
I said I'd talk to you about it.
The Ravinok was
a Cardassian ship.
Carrying Bajoran prisoners.
No, I'm not stopping
anyone else from looking.
I just don't see why
they have to come with me.
The request came directly
from the leader
of the new civilian government.
Nerys...
I know this isn't
what you had in mind
but Bajor and Cardassia
must learn to work together
and that means cooperating
on missions like these.
All right.
Just tell them
I'm not going to wait forever.
If their representative
isn't here
within 52 hours,
I'm going alone.
I'll be sure
they get the message.
So, did you and Kasidy
have a nice time last night?
Huh. I just wish she
wasn't leaving tomorrow.
Sounds like the two of you
are getting serious.
I don't know about that.
I don't think Kasidy is
looking to get serious.
Ben!
Kasidy!
We were just talking about you.
I don't mean to interrupt.
I wanted you to know
that I won't be leaving
tomorrow after all.
Ah, that's good news.
I mean, that's great.
How long are you
going to be here?
Well, that depends
on whether I get
this new job or not.
I've, uh, applied for a position
with the Bajoran
Ministry of Commerce
to captain
one of their freighters.
You're going to work
for the Bajorans?
If we can hammer
out an agreement.
It's a terrific opportunity.
I get to use my own ship,
pick my own crew
and the best part is
I never have
to leave this sector.
Where are you going to live?
On my ship, I suppose.
Well, why don't you stay here?
I'm sure that Benjamin
could arrange for some quarters.
That's, uh...
not a bad idea.
Yeah.
Well, I... have
a meeting on Bajor
and the shuttle leaves
in a few minutes.
I'll see you tonight?
That answers that.
She's serious.
Captain...
the Cardassian Transport Rabol
is approaching the station.
They are requesting
permission to beam
their representative
directly to Ops.
Someone's in a big hurry.
Permission granted.
Aye, sir.
Ah!
Major Kira.
I'm ready to leave
whenever you are.
We'll be crossing
into the Badlands
in approximately six hours.
Very good, Major.
Dukat, let's get
one thing straight.
This is my mission.
The only reason you're here
is because I agreed
to let you come along.
When I give an order,
I expect you to follow it
no questions asked.
Believe me, Major,
I want nothing more
than for this mission
to be concluded
as quickly and as efficiently
as possible
and I leave the details
in your capable hands.
Good. Then we shouldn't
have any problems.
There's one thing
I don't understand.
Why did the Cardassian
government send you?
The Ravinok was under
my general command.
Those were my troops
and it is my duty
to try to find them.
The question is,
what are you doing here, Major?
I knew someone
aboard the Ravinok.
One of the prisoners, I assume?
Lorit Akrem.
I see.
So you're on this mission
for personal reasons.
Is there something wrong
with that?
No, not at all.
I've found that when one
has a difficult job to do
personal reasons can be
quite an incentive.
So who was he?
A family member, a compatriot...
a lover?
Lorit recruited me into
the Shakaar resistance cell.
Ah...
the infamous Shakaar resistance.
We never could eliminate
that little group of yours.
And it was not from lack
of trying, I can assure you.
I... hope you don't take this
the wrong way, Major
but I've always admired you.
You are the embodiment
of the new Bajor...
a Bajoran born out of the ashes
of the occupation.
A Bajoran tempered
with Cardassian steel.
Oh, Captain Sisko's right.
You are in love with
the sound of your own voice.
I know you find this
hard to accept, but...
I believe that, in some ways
the occupation
actually helped Bajor.
Which part?
The massacres
or the strip mining?
I have no desire
to debate the merits
of the occupation with you.
I'm even willing to admit that
perhaps we were a little harsh
in our methods, but the fact is,
the Bajoran people
are stronger now than they
have been in centuries.
When we arrived, you were
a weak, contemplative race
choking on your isolation
and now you have
a new confidence
a whole new sense of purpose
not to mention a key role
in the future
of this entire Quadrant.
All of which Bajor accomplished
in spite of the Cardassians
not because of them.
Think what you must
but I believe the time will come
when Cardassia
and Bajor will grow
to be not only allies
but also close friends.
Bajor and Cardassia, maybe.
You and me...
I doubt it.
All I ask is that
you have an open mind.
All right, Dukat, that's enough.
Now, if you don't mind
I would like to spend
the next six hours
in silent meditation.
Is that a request or an order?
Whatever it takes.
Well, in that case,
as much as it pains me...
Hmm.
We both might survive
this trip after all.
They didn't even wait
for the interview to be over.
After 20 minutes, Minister Azin
said she'd heard enough
and if I wanted the job,
it was mine.
So what did you tell them?
What do you think I told them?
I said yes.
Congratulations.
That's it?
Oh.
That's...
that's not what I meant.
I want to know
how you feel about it.
Well... I think it's great.
We'll see a lot more
of each other.
You know, I was thinking
about what Dax said.
Maybe I should get
quarters on the station.
That's a big step.
What does that mean?
Well, I just meant...
it's a big step.
A bad big step
or a good big step?
A good one.
Could you muster up
a little more enthusiasm?
I am enthusiastic.
I'm proud of you.
This job...
Forget about the job.
I'm talking about us.
I tell you I'm thinking
about living on the station
and all you can say is,
"it's a big step"?
Oh, I don't think you took it
the way I meant it.
I don't think you know
what you meant, but I do.
You're afraid of commitment.
Who said anything
about commitment?
Obviously not you.
You... you know what?
Forget the whole thing.
I'm not going to take the job.
If you don't want me
to stay here
that's fine with me.
Whew!
How'd you get ahold of this,
Razka?
I bought it off
a Ferengi scrap-metal merchant.
Hmm... it appears to be
composed of uridium alloy.
It's definitely Cardassian.
Can you tell if it's
from the Ravinok?
Why didn't you tell me
you were bringing him along?
Because when we talked,
I didn't know I would be.
Too bad.
The Maquis would've
paid handsomely
to get their hands on him.
And my government
would be very happy
to get its hands on you.
Razka Karn, if I'm not mistaken.
Smuggler, thief,
black marketeer.
There are at least
12 outstanding warrants
for your arrest
on Cardassia right now
but I suggest
we ignore all that
and try to cooperate
with one another.
The voice of the new Cardassia...
so compassionate,
so understanding.
Almost makes you forget
that five years ago
he was working
Bajorans to death
in forced labor camps
and shooting anybody
who tried to stop him.
Almost makes you forget.
It's from the Ravinok...
no doubt about it.
Did the Ferengi tell you
where he found it?
No, but I was curious
so I bribed one
of his crew members.
Turns out his last trip
was to the Dozaria system.
Dozaria...
I believe there is one
Class-M planet in that system.
Barely Class-M.
He found that in orbit.
Dozaria it is, then.
Thanks, Razka.
I owe you one.
Just let me know
what you find out.
Lorit was my friend, too.
I just don't understand
how the Ravinok
could have gotten
so far off course.
Dozaria's light years away
from where they
should have been.
The Central Command
always believed
that the ship was destroyed
in some sort of escape attempt
by the Bajoran prisoners.
Maybe.
Or they could
have had a problem
with their navigational array
or run into some kind
of subspace anomaly.
Hopefully, we'll find the truth.
We're entering orbit.
Hmm... I'm reading
severe ionic interference
in the planet's atmosphere.
Sensors will be limited,
to say the least.
I'm picking up
a faint magneton signature.
It could be residual radiation
from a damaged warp nacelle.
Shall we beam down?
I wouldn't advise it.
All this ionic interference
will scatter our molecules
halfway around the planet.
We're going to have to do this
the old-fashioned way.
It's going to be
a difficult landing.
I'll take the controls
if you like.
That'll be the day.
Going in.
Invigorating, isn't it?
A bit sunny, perhaps
but this heat feels wonderful.
Only a Cardassian
would call
this hellhole invigorating.
Oh, I forgot.
Compared to us, you Bajorans
are a bit fragile...
physiologically
speaking, of course.
Don't worry about me.
The Ravinok.
"It's a big step."
That's all you said?
That's all.
You're sure?
Positive.
What do you think, Julian?
It's ambiguous; definitely
open to interpretation.
But it could have been worse.
He could have said,
"It's a very big step."
You didn't say that, did you?
I don't think so.
Well, that's good, anyway.
So what does he do now?
It's simple.
He goes to Kasidy
admits that everything
was his fault
and pledges his undying love.
That sounds
a little extreme to me.
What if he just tells her
he made a mistake?
That there had been
a misunderstanding
and that he really
would like her
to live on the station?
Could work.
Assuming that's what you want.
Captain, I would
think long and hard
before answering.
I don't recall asking
your opinion, Quark.
Well, maybe you should.
I mean, who knows more
about women than me?
Everyone.
You hu-mans...
all you want to do
is please your women.
You want them to be your friends
but we Ferengi know better.
Women are the enemy
and we treat them accordingly.
The key is to never let them
get the upper hand.
If she says she
doesn't see you enough
threaten to see her even less.
If she wants more gifts
take back the ones
you've already given her.
It's all about control.
What if your woman leaves you?
That's what holosuites are for.
It's a wonder the Ferengi
reproduce at all.
So, you never answered
the question.
Do you want her to stay or not?
I appreciate all the advice.
I'll let you know
how it turns out.
So, just between you and me,
what do you think
about Kasidy moving
onto the station?
It's a big step.
A very big step.
Oh, she didn't just crash.
These are phaser hits.
Looks like she put up
quite a fight.
And paid for it.
12 graves.
There were 18 crew members
and 32 prisoners aboard.
So where's everybody else?
First things first.
What are you doing?
We need to identify
these bodies.
I'll help.
No!
Our funeral rites
are very strict.
It would dishonor the dead
for a non-Cardassian
to view the remains.
There could be Bajorans
buried here, too.
No doubt.
But, if my memory's correct
Bajorans are much more concerned
with the souls of the dead
than they are
with the physical remains.
How did Kai Meressa put it?
"What remains after death
is but a shell... a sign
"that the pagh has begun
its final journey
to the Prophets."
Please, Major, don't make this
any more difficult for me
than it already is.
I have a list
of the missing Bajorans.
I should be able
to identify them
from the family imprint
on the earrings.
I'll work on the Ravinok.
I should be able
to get something
from the ship's computers.
You'll need the command codes.
Standard Cardassian
military codes
from six years ago, right?
Yes.
Yeah, I got them
from Bajoran Intelligence
before we left.
Very good, Major.
Very good.
Dukat...
I was able to reactivate the...
Dukat.
What was her name?
I recognize a Bajoran pledge
bracelet when I see one.
Her name was Tora... Naprem.
You see, Major...
you're not the only one...
who had a friend
aboard that ship.
A friend... is that all she was?
I see.
Don't worry, Dukat.
You're not
the only Cardassian officer
who kept a Bajoran mistress.
It wasn't like that.
Naprem and I...
Loved each other.
The head of the occupation...
in love with a Bajoran?
Ironic, isn't it?
Did your wife know?
No...
and she's never going
to find out.
Now, if you don't mind, Major
I'd rather not talk
about this right now.
Here are the earrings
you wanted.
No...
If Lorit's dead...
he's not buried here.
According
to the ship's computers
the Ravinok was attacked
by two unidentified warships.
The attackers chased
the Ravinok here
and must have forced her
to crash land.
Then the survivors
could have been captured
and taken away.
Or they could still be here,
somewhere on this planet.
Maybe we should go up
in the runabout
and scan for them from orbit.
Too much ionic interference.
The sensors would never be able
to pick up their life signs.
There may be another way.
In these conditions,
tricorder readings
will only be about 12 meters,
but that should be enough.
Enough for what?
During the occupation,
Bajoran resistance fighters
carried subdermal implants
of tritonium isotopes.
The idea was
that if they were captured
they could activate the implant
which would leave
a trail of isotopes
so they could be
tracked and rescued.
I think I have something.
That way.
Let's go.
I don't know
why we have to stop.
For one thing...
I can't see two meters
in front of us
and, anyway, we could
both use the rest.
So stop pacing and sit down.
What is it?!
Oh! Oh! I don't know.
I sat on something.
I sat on something!
Let me see.
Oh!
Oh, get it out.
Well, keep still
and let me see what I can do.
Get it out!
Oh, this is going to hurt.
It already hurts.
Just take it out.
If you say so.
Ow!
Oh... oh...
Ouch.
Run this dermal regenerator
over the wound.
Ooh.
This isn't funny!
It is from this angle.
You know what's even funnier?
This doesn't work.
You...
have to...
activate it.
Oh.
Oh, oh, yes.
Oh, much better.
Oh.
You probably should
eat one of these.
Ah...
I haven't had field rations
in a very long time.
I'm sure they haven't
improved a bit.
Actually, they've gotten
a little worse.
Tell me something.
What?
Who's Tora Ziyal?
When I reactivated
the Ravinok's computer, I...
downloaded the manifest.
There were two civilians
on board
in addition to the prisoners
and crew.
One... was your friend...
Tora Naprem...
and the other...
was Tora Ziyal...
a 13-year-old girl.
I suppose you wouldn't...
believe me if I told you
she was Naprem's sister?
Mm-mm.
Ziyal is a Cardassian name.
The way I see it...
there's only one explanation.
Ziyal
was Naprem's daughter,
and you...
I was her father.
Well...
now I know why you're in such
a hurry to find the survivors.
You're hoping that...
Oh.
...she's still alive
and you can rescue her.
Not quite.
You see, if my daughter
is still alive
I'll have no choice
but to kill her.
You know I'm not going
to let you do it.
I mean it, Dukat.
You are not going
to kill that girl.
Major, why don't you worry
about the other survivors
and let me worry about Ziyal.
After all, she is my daughter.
That's right...
she's your daughter.
And there is nothing
more important
to a Cardassian than family.
At least, that's what your
people are always saying.
I have a wife
and seven children.
They are my family.
They're the ones I must protect.
Well, you should have
thought of that
before you got
involved with Naprem.
You're right.
I should have.
But I made a mistake...
a mistake I intend to correct.
You don't have to take her
back to Cardassia with you.
Let me take her to Bajor.
No one has to know
that you're her father.
What kind of life
would that be for her?
Your people have
never exactly welcomed
half-Cardassian children
into your society.
That's why I sent her
and her mother away
in the first place.
I knew the occupation
was coming to an end
and that there'd be
no place for them
on Bajor or Cardassia.
So you sent them
to a prison camp.
They were not on their way
to a prison camp!
The Ravinok was supposed to
rendezvous with a freighter
which would take Naprem
and Ziyal to Lissepia
where they could live out
their lives
in some sort of peace.
I don't understand.
If you cared enough
to help Ziyal then
how can you think
about killing her now?
Why not just send her
away again?
Because my position isn't nearly
as stable as it once was.
By aligning myself
with the new civilian government
I've made many enemies, enemies
that wouldn't hesitate
to use Ziyal against me.
Listen to you!
It's not your wife
and your seven children
you're protecting, it's you.
By protecting myself,
I am protecting them.
And the only one
who suffers is Ziyal.
You would kill your own
daughter to save your career.
I don't understand you.
You said you loved Naprem.
I saw you crying at her grave.
I...
did love her.
And when I bury Ziyal,
I'll weep over her grave
just as I wept over her mother's
but that will not stop me
from doing what I have to do.
Do you understand?
And when the time comes
I suggest you stay
out of my way.
Good morning, Jake-o.
Morning, Dad.
So...
what's new?
Nog and I
ran into Kasidy last night
over at the, uh,
Vulcan restaurant.
I guess she's not going to take
that job after all.
She told you?
Did she say why?
She said you didn't
want her to take it.
Look, Jake...
sometimes things
between men and women
can get a little...
complicated.
Yeah, maybe, but I
don't think this is
one of those times.
It's pretty simple, Dad.
You're scared.
What do I have to be afraid of?
A lot.
Kasidy's willing to make
a major change in her life
just to be close to you.
If things don't work out,
you're going to feel responsible
and that's scary.
You figured out
all this by yourself?
Actually, I talked
with Nog about it.
You talked to Nog about
my relationship with Kasidy?
And we think
you have nothing to worry about.
If Kasidy wants to change jobs,
that's her decision, not yours.
Same thing if she wants to live
on the station.
If things don't work out,
they don't work out.
Have you told
any of this to Kasidy?
Nog and I thought about it,
but, uh...
we thought it would be better
if you told her yourself.
I see.
So, uh, what's new with you?
Take a look.
Breen?
What are they doing here?
My tricorder's picking up
a large concentration
of dilithium in the area.
They must be using
the survivors of the
Ravinok to mine the ore.
It makes perfect sense.
The Breen homeworld
is a frozen wasteland.
This place is about 50
degrees too hot for them.
You approve
of what they're doing?
No! Not at all.
I do admire their ingenuity.
What is it?
It's her.
My daughter.
All right, we're going
to need some help.
I'm going to stay here
and keep an eye on things
while you go back to DS9
for reinforcements.
I have a better idea.
You go back to the station.
I'll stay here.
I'm sending you back, Dukat.
That's an order.
And I hate to refuse it,
but I'm afraid I must.
You're welcome to file
an official protest
with the Cardassian military
when we get back.
There's no way
I'm leaving you here alone.
Well...
then I suggest we devise a plan
to rescue
these prisoners together.
You need me, Major.
Maybe I do.
But if you hurt that girl...
I promise I'll kill you.
Don't make any noise.
We're here to help.
You're Bajoran!
Gather up as many prisoners
as you can.
Tell them to meet us here.
How many Breen guards
are there?
I'm not sure.
There are always at least
eight in the mines.
How many prisoners?
There are only 31 of us left.
What about Lorit Akrem?
Did he make it?
He died in a cave-in
two years ago.
You knew him?
He was a friend.
My condolences, Major,
but we don't have time for this.
Tell me where I can find
Tora Ziyal?
Don't tell him anything.
He's a Cardassian.
I don't understand.
There's a peace treaty.
You mean the occupation is over?
I need to find the girl!
Where is she?
Dukat!
Go get the rest
of the prisoners.
Meet me at the entrance
to the mine.
Where is Tora Ziyal?
Ziyal.
Father?
Oh, it's really you.
Mother said you'd...
Father, what's wrong?
Dukat, no!
I'm warning you, Dukat.
Don't do it.
I have no choice.
There's always a choice.
You don't want to do this.
If you did, you never would
have told me about Ziyal.
Now put the rifle down.
No.
The Cardassian prisoners...
they told me this would happen.
That you'd never let me go home
but I-I-I didn't,
didn't believe them.
Ziyal, run!
I used to dream about you
coming to save me.
That's what kept me alive.
Ziyal...
If I can't be with you...
then I'd rather die.
Let's go home.
Kasidy Yates.
Hello, Ben.
Hold this a second.
About that job
with the Bajoran
Commerce Ministry...
You know someone
who's qualified for it?
I know someone who would
be perfect for it... you.
I think you
should take the job.
I want you to take the job.
You've been talking to Jake.
How'd you know?
Oh, he's a smart boy.
Must take after his mother.
I owe you an apology.
You came to tell me
all this wonderful news
and all I could say was,
"It's a big step."
I don't know
what I was thinking.
Take a guess.
I wanted to tell you
how happy I was
for you... f-for us
but it didn't come out that way.
I...
I was uncomfortable
and a little nervous.
A little nervous?
All right.
A lot nervous.
I haven't been
in a serious relationship
for a long time, and I didn't
expect to be in one
any time soon...
until I met you.
This life I lead...
this job I do...
that's what got Jennifer killed.
If anything ever
happened to you...
Why not let me
worry about that?
That's what Jake said.
You see? Smart boy.
Look, I could stay here
and listen to you
apologize all day
but I've got to get to Bajor.
Bajor?
I thought...
Oh, I know what you thought
but I took the job.
Do you think I'd give
up a great opportunity
just because you got cold feet?
You're a good man,
Benjamin Sisko
but you've got a lot
to learn about women...
especially this one.
I'll see you when I get back.
You can... help me
pick out quarters.
I'll be here.
What was it like...
all that time alone with Dukat?
I've had better weeks
but I'll never forget
the look on his face
when he sat on that sand spine.
I wish I'd been there.
Major.
Dukat.
Where's Ziyal?
Waiting for me aboard my ship.
We'll be leaving
for Cardassia shortly.
I think I'll leave
the two of you alone.
I just wanted to say...
thank you, Major
for a most interesting journey.
You're taking Ziyal back
to Cardassia with you.
After six years,
she deserves a home...
and a father.
Won't that make things
difficult for you?
I'll let you know.