It's a trick.
Of course, it's a trick,
but how did she do it?
She probably beamed the egg
directly into her mouth
from one of
the transporters.
Actually,
one of my previous hosts
used to dabble
in the sleight of hand.
Was it Tobin?
DAX: That's right.
Ah, he sounds like
the right type--
painfully shy,
introverted,
a slight lack
of confidence--
just the kind of person
who might want to dazzle
the world with his
magical abilities.
She swallowed the egg
before she came into the bar
and then
regurgitated it on cue.
Quite disgusting, actually.
Wrong again.
( beeping )
Sisko to Dax.
I'd like to see you
in my office, Commander.
On my way, Benjamin.
Don't worry, Quark.
You'll figure it out eventually.
What?
No wonder
you can't figure it out.
Your head's full
of latinum.
( laughs )
Ladies and gentlemen,
the amazing Jadzia Dax.
Have a seat.
A Trill science team
is coming to the station
to conduct field tests
on experimental techniques
for creating
artificial wormholes.
It sounds interesting.
It's an important
project,
and I've agreed
to let them use
the Defiant for
their experiments.
But I thought you
would want to know
that the leader
of the science team
is Dr. Lenara Kahn.
Lenara Kahn.
That's right.
Look, you've got
about three months
of leave accumulated.
Why don't you
take some of it?
We can afford to do without you
for a while.
Am I that dispensable
around here?
We'll never notice you're gone.
No.
I'll stay.
I can handle it.
You're sure.
I'm sure.
I've never let my past lives
interfere with my job,
and I'm not going to start now.
I'll be fine.
Okay.
But...
thank you
for giving me the option.
Anytime, old man.
I'm Dr. Hanor Pren
of the Trill Science Ministry.
I'm Major Kira Nerys,
and I'd like to welcome you
to Deep Space 9.
This is our Strategic Operations
Officer, Commander Worf,
and this is our Science Officer,
Commander Dax.
Allow me to introduce you
to our team leader
Dr. Lenara Kahn and her brother,
Dr. Bejal Otner.
Major Kira,
Commander Worf,
and Commander Dax.
It's been a long time.
Yes, it has.
If you will come with me,
I will show you
to your quarters.
You know that woman.
I know her.
She used to be my wife.
So let me get this straight.
Dax's first host
was named Lela, right?
I think so.
Lela Dax.
That's right.
Then Lela dies
and the Dax symbiont goes on
to a man named Tobin,
and after Tobin dies,
then it's on to Emony,
then Torias,
Audrid...
No, no. Audrid, then Torias.
Sorry.
Audrid, Torias, Joran, Curzon
and then eventually, Jadzia.
Right.
And this, uh, Dr. Lenara Kahn
person was once married to...?
Torias, but, of course, in
those days, she wasn't Lenara.
I knew
it couldn't be that simple.
And the Kahn symbiont,
which is now joined to Lenara
used to be joined to
a woman named Nilani.
And it was Nilani who
married Torias Dax.
But Torias was killed
in a shuttle accident.
And Nilani
became a widow.
Years later,
when Nilani died,
the Kahn symbiont
was joined to Lenara.
And now, Nilani is Lenara,
and Torias is Jadzia.
So that makes Lenara
Jadzia's ex-wife.
It's a little more complicated
than that, Quark.
I'm sure it is,
but to be honest,
I'm sorry I brought
the whole thing up.
It's giving me a headache.
It must be
all the latinum
rattling
around in there.
Oh.
I thought so.
You really should
have that looked at.
Get back to work!
If you'll
excuse me...
Dax teach
you that?
Next time, I'm
going to pull
a rabbit out
of his ear.
The one thing
I don't understand
is why Dax and Lenara
can't just pick up
where they left off--
I mean, if they're still
in love with each other.
Ah, now there's the rub.
Even if they do harbor
feelings for each other,
it's strictly against
the rules of Trill society
for them to acknowledge
it in any way.
Rules?
Well, it's more
of a taboo, really.
Having a relationship
with a lover
from a past life
is called a reassociation.
And the Trill feel very strongly
that it's... unnatural.
Unnatural?
How can it be unnatural
for a married couple
to resume their marriage?
Well, the
whole point
of joining is for the symbiont
to accumulate experiences
from the span of many lifetimes.
In order to move on
from host to host,
the symbiont has to learn
to let go of the past,
let go of parents, siblings,
children, even spouses.
I don't understand
how two people
who have fallen in love
and made a life together
can be forced to just walk away
from each other
because of a taboo.
No. There must be some Trill
who have reassociated
with people
from their past lives.
I asked Dax
the same question.
It seems there
have been a few.
And what happened?
They were exiled
from the Trill homeworld.
That means the symbionts would
never be joined to a new host.
Exactly.
So when the hosts die,
the symbionts die with them.
So, you see, even if Dax
does harbor feelings for Lenara,
she can't take that risk.
For a joined Trill,
nothing is more important
than to protect
the life of the symbiont.
Nothing.
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Come in.
I had the feeling
you weren't going to be ready.
Curzon was never
on time in his life.
He was even late
for his 100th
birthday party.
You're never going to let me
forget that, are you?
Do you know how long
it took me to plan that party?
Three months.
I know.
You still have time to back
out of the reception, you know.
Oh, you know
how I hate to miss a party.
I'm serious.
I know.
And I appreciate
what you're trying to do,
but I'm going to be working
with Lenara for the next week.
I have to get used
to being around her.
Stop worrying about me,
Benjamin.
I'll be fine.
( conversation and laughter )
So, in the spirit of friendship,
we welcome you to Deep Space 9
and wish you success
in the creation
of the galaxy's
first artificial wormhole.
Hear, hear.
I understand you'll
be commanding
the Defiant
during our research.
Yes.
You must be very excited.
I mean, to be part
of a potentially
history-making project.
I am...
looking forward to it.
I think Mr. Worf is
less than enthusiastic
about heading
a research mission.
It's not exactly
what every Klingon
dreams about.
What do Klingons
dream about?
Things that would send
cold chills down your spine
and wake you
in the middle
of the night.
No, no. It is better
you do not know.
Excuse me.
I can never tell
when he's joking.
Maybe it is better
that we do not know.
( both laughing )
Well, this
looks wonderful.
Mm-hmm.
I take it most
of this is Bajoran.
Hasperat.
Uh...
No.
Hasperat.
Moba fruit
and veklava.
Of course, I'm not
the least bit hungry.
Neither am I.
But I suppose we should
load up our plates
since the whole room
is watching us.
Quite an audience.
Seems a shame
to disappoint them.
Maybe we should
do something.
Well, we could get
into a screaming match
and start throwing
things at each other.
Not bad.
Or I suppose we could throw
ourselves at each other,
profess our undying
love for each other
in complete disregard
for Trill society.
Dr. Pren would probably
have a heart attack.
Forget about him.
My brother's head
would explode.
He's been a nervous wreck
ever since we arrived.
I know the feeling.
Well, I'll tell you
what I told him.
We're both mature adults,
and we can handle this.
I agree completely.
It'll be fine.
They're watching us again.
I know.
I guess we'll probably
have to get used to it.
Well...
thank you, Commander Dax.
I appreciate your insightful
commentary on Bajoran cuisine.
My pleasure, Dr. Kahn.
BEJAL: After we launch
our target drone,
the Defiant
will have to generate
a subspace tensor matrix
in the 25,000 to 30,000
Cochrane range.
Then the drone will send out
a magneton pulse,
which should
react with the matrix
to create an opening
in the space-time continuum.
How long will we have
to keep generating
the matrix?
Two minutes, maybe less.
Once the wormhole
forms, we could shut
down the tensor matrix.
O'BRIEN:
We'll have to reroute
the preignition plasma
from the impulse deck
down to the auxiliary intake
to generate that much power,
but I think we can do it.
Excellent.
We'll also need to
download our parameters
for the matrix into
one of your computers.
I think we'd better use
the main computer, Chief.
I don't think the Engineering
computer can handle it.
I agree.
If you'll follow me,
I'll take you up to the Bridge
and we can begin
downloading the data.
All right.
Everything looks good here.
Dax?
The backup navigation program
is still showing
some calibration drift.
I think some data
may have been lost
in the start-up routine.
Possibly.
Well... that explains
the seven percent falloff
in AFR ratios I keep seeing.
Must be a problem
in the diagnostic subroutines.
I have a recalibration
unit in my quarters
that might
solve the problem.
I'll have someone
bring it here.
Oh, no, no,
I need a break anyway.
( door opens, closes )
Now I'm getting a drop-off
in the triple-R output.
We might have
a bigger problem
than the diagnostic
subroutines.
Don't panic yet.
It could just be
transtator failure.
It happens
all the time.
I wasn't panicking.
It's just
an expression.
Sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
( chuckles )
Forget it.
You know, it's just
that you always used to...
I mean, Torias always
used to tell Nilani
that she was panicking
about things,
making a big fuss
about nothing.
Well, Torias used to be
insensitive at times.
But you have to admit
Nilani did do her share
of overreacting.
That's because
you were a pilot,
and it made me nervous...
made her nervous.
Torias being a pilot
made Nilani nervous.
I've never had
quite this much trouble
sorting out my feelings
from those of a past host.
I know what you mean.
Probably another good reason
why we're not supposed
to spend much time together.
We'd probably just
get lost in the past.
Let's try running
the transtator diagnostic again.
Okay.
Nilani wasn't panicking
the day before Torias died.
No?
No.
Torias should have listened
to her.
The shuttle was not ready
for a full impulse test,
but Torias had to do it anyway.
And he was wrong,
and whatever part of me
is still Torias...
is very sorry...
and wishes he'd listened to you.
Well...
we have a lot of work to do.
Right.
Would you be interested
in dinner?
I mean,
I'm having dinner
with some friends,
and I thought
you might like to go along.
Oh, I-I wouldn't want
to intrude on your friends.
Actually, it's not
that big of a group.
It's just me and...
Julian.
Dr. Bashir?
Sure.
That sounds great.
Great.
Okay.
Dinner,
tonight.
At Quark's.
Great.
Tonight?
I can't.
I have plans.
Cancel them.
I mean, if you can cancel them,
that would be really nice.
Nice.
Yeah.
Because...?
Because I invited Lenara
out for dinner and...
And it would be less awkward
if you had a chaperon.
Exactly.
Will you do it?
Something tells me
that I should say no,
but you know I won't.
What time?
2200 at Quark's.
Thank you.
I owe you one.
No, it didn't have
a red awning.
It had a big ratana tree
or something out front.
Well, you don't mean
the Barros Inn?
Yes, that's it.
Curzon was kicked out
of the Barros Inn.
That's one of the wildest bars
in the whole Rigel system.
What did he do?
He sort of
set fire to it.
Sort of.
All right,
he set fire to it,
but it wasn't deliberate.
It was part of a bet.
But that's another story.
Curzon was certainly...
different from
most joined Trills.
Yeah, he liked to do things
his own way.
He used to say there was
an exception to every rule,
and he usually went
out of his way to find it.
I'm actually glad
we never met.
We probably wouldn't have
liked each other very much.
No, he wasn't
that bad, really.
I tend to exaggerate
his rebellious qualities.
But you may have
a point.
Curzon never had
much use for scientists.
Well, that's interesting,
considering what you do now.
Curzon would be horrified
to know that I'm a scientist.
Oh, the very idea
of doing research made him ill.
Torias wasn't
much different.
I can remember talking to him
about my wanting to study
theoretical quantum physics
and his eyes glazing over.
The irony is, you and I
have more in common
than Torias and Nilani ever did.
That's right.
MEDICAL OFFICER:
Infirmary to Dr. Bashir.
Um, Dr. Bashir here.
Go ahead.
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
Doctor,
but Ensign Tyler
has broken his leg and...
Oh, I'm on my way.
Um, I'm sorry.
Uh, I must go.
Duty calls.
That's all right.
Thanks for coming.
LENARA:
It was nice
to see you again.
Now, that's a good friend.
I mean,
he sat here all night,
listening to us trade stories
of our former hosts
and never once complained.
I think he enjoyed himself.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe not.
No.
( both laughing )
I'll make it up to him.
Yeah.
Those are Klingon, aren't they?
Yeah. How did you know?
Curzon.
They're beautiful.
Yeah.
They were given to me
by a, uh, Klingon scientist.
He wanted to give me
one of the swords
they carry around,
but I refused.
Keep them.
Really.
I'm not very Klingon.
Thanks.
Well?
They suit you.
It's really good
to see you again, Dax.
Oh, that sounds
so strange.
I mean, I'm looking
at a different face,
hearing a different voice...
but somehow it's still you.
I know.
Every time
I start to think of you
as just Lenara,
you'll smile, or laugh,
and suddenly it's you.
I'm really glad you're here.
Me, too.
WORF:
Defiant Log, Stardate 49195.5.
Lieutenant Commander Worf
reporting.
We have arrived
at the coordinates
to begin preliminary tests
for the artificial
wormhole project.
Target drone is in position,
Commander.
Full scan.
No ships in sensor range.
Bridge to
Engineering.
Are you ready, Mr. Eddington?
EDDINGTON:
We're ready, Commander.
Dr. Kahn... you may proceed.
Energize the focal array
and stand by to initiate
the subspace tensor matrix.
This AQF sequencer
is always causing
me problems.
Plasma coil interlocks
are in place.
Deflector grid is charged
and standing by.
They're very
friendly today.
Hmm?
They had dinner
last night... alone.
What are you
trying to say?
I shouldn't have
to say anything.
Then don't.
We're ready to generate
the tensor matrix.
The drone is standing by.
Initialize
the focal array.
BEJAL:
The tensor matrix is forming.
Activate the drone.
The drone is sending out
the magneton pulse.
It's reached the matrix.
I'm picking up
a subspace distortion.
BEJAL:
The distortion's
becoming coherent.
It's working.
DAX:
The magneton pulse
is causing a feedback loop.
It'll destroy the drone
in a few seconds.
A few seconds is all we need.
The drone's
been destroyed.
But you did it.
Congratulations, Doctor.
Thank you.
That was only the first step,
but what a step.
I'm so proud.
Thank you.
LENARA:
...the subspace field data,
the quantum readings--
all the telemetry
checks out.
The wormhole was
open 23.4 seconds,
and during that time,
it was completely coherent.
You couldn't ask
for a better beginning.
But it all comes down
to the next test.
We have to be able to send
an object through the wormhole
to prove that it's stable
for space travel.
Oh, that reminds me.
Dax thinks we should use
a class-4 probe
to make the actual run with.
She says that
the class-4 shielding
will give us a better idea
of how the wormhole
will affect a real ship.
I didn't know you'd talked
to Dax since we got back.
Yeah, I saw her last night.
Where?
She came by my quarters.
How long did she stay?
Is there something
you want to ask me?
I don't want
to ask you anything,
but I'm beginning to wonder
if I should.
I don't believe this.
Believe it.
People are starting to notice.
People?
Dr. Pren saw you holding hands
at dinner the other night.
I thought he was overreacting,
but then I saw the way
the two of you were acting
on the Defiant.
Lenara.
Lenara. Lenara.
I'm sorry.
Look, I'm your brother.
You tell me
nothing's going on...
then nothing's going on.
I just want
to hear you say it.
There is nothing
going on.
All right?
All right.
( exhaling )
( door chimes )
Come in.
( sighs )
What's wrong?
I just had the most
unpleasant conversation
with my brother.
He...
he thinks that there's something
going on between us.
Oh.
And what did you tell him?
Well, I told him
that that was ridiculous.
That there's nothing
going on between us.
That you and I are just friends.
Well, then,
that should settle that.
Maybe we shouldn't
see each other.
It'll just give people
the wrong idea.
Or give them the right idea.
I don't think we should have
this conversation.
Would it do any good?
Would it change
how either of us feels?
No.
But it would be easier.
You've never been one
for the easy way out.
That's true,
but in this case...
I'm not the only one involved.
I don't want to do
anything to hurt you.
I did that before.
I climbed into
a shuttlecraft,
and I made you a widow.
I knew you were a pilot
when I married you.
I knew the risks.
I went into it
with my eyes wide open.
And what about now?
Are your eyes open?
Do you know
what the risks are?
I thought I'd...
I thought I'd gotten over you.
It's been so long
and so much has happened.
And now I know I haven't.
Shh.
Shh, shh.
I've missed you.
I've missed you so much.
I'd better go.
Yeah.
DAX: I don't know
what to do, Benjamin.
What do you want to do?
Throw myself at her,
profess my undying love
and my complete disregard
for Trill society.
A joke Lenara made
at the reception.
It doesn't sound so funny
anymore, does it?
Not really.
You don't think
I should pursue this, do you?
No.
Okay.
Why?
Because I remember what Curzon
used to say about reassociation,
that it didn't matter whether
he agreed with the taboo or not,
because the price
for violating it was too high--
exile.
I know
what Curzon
used to say...
and I'm not Curzon.
And you're not
Torias either.
You're Jadzia Dax,
and you have a responsibility
as a joined Trill to never...
I didn't come here
to hear a lecture
about my responsibilities.
You came here
for advice from a friend,
and that's exactly
what you're getting.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I know this is difficult
for you.
I know how you feel
about Lenara,
but I want you to think
about what will happen
if you pursue this.
If you're exiled from Trill,
there will be no further hosts
for your symbiont.
When Jadzia dies,
Dax dies.
That goes against
everything you were taught
during your
initiate training.
You've told me again and again
that each host
is only a link in a chain...
and that the life
of the symbiont,
no matter what happens,
must go on.
I know that...
and I believe in that.
But I also know...
I love her, Benjamin.
( sighs )
I know you do.
If I were in your position,
I'd probably be just as ready
to throw away everything
for the person I love.
But I would also
want to be sure
that I was ready
to pay the price.
You're right.
I need to be sure.
But if you're sure...
if this is what
you really want...
I will back you all the way.
I've lived seven lifetimes,
and I have never had
a friend quite like you.
Eddington to Bridge.
We're ready to generate
the tensor matrix.
Understood.
Stand by.
Aye, sir.
Commander Dax.
Subspace field stress is
within normal parameters.
Probe's ready to launch.
Target drone is in position.
Bridge to Engine Room.
Initialize subspace matrix,
Mr. Eddington.
WORF:
On my mark.
Acknowledged.
BEJAL:
The tensor matrix
is starting to form.
Activate the drone.
Wormhole neutrino readings
are stable.
Subspace field stress
is up by 15 percent,
but still within safety margins.
Launch the probe.
( alarm blaring )
Report!
No helm control!
There's a hull breach
on deck five.
Emergency force fields
are in place.
I'm reading
a massive plasma leak
in the Engine Room.
WORF:
Bridge to
Engine Room!
Mr. Eddington!
Dr. Kahn, can you hear me?
Have a damage control team
meet me down there.
Stand back.
EDDINGTON:
It's out of control!
We can't put it
out with those!
We'll have to vent the entire
compartment out into space.
No! Lenara might
still be alive.
There's no way
to get to her.
How long will a level-A
force field last in here?
Not long with
that plasma fire.
Ten, 20 seconds
at most.
I think I can get to her.
Dax, if we don't
contain this thing now,
it's going
to set off the warp core.
I know,
just give me ten seconds
after the force field
goes off,
and then vent
the compartment.
I need to reconfigure
the field geometry.
I'll try to
keep the field
stable as long as I can.
( alarm beeps )
( gasping )
Oh, Dax...
I thought I'd lost you.
Oh, so did I.
I don't want to lose you.
Not again.
Never again.
Never again. Never.
( door chimes )
Come in.
How are you
feeling?
Much better.
She's almost
fully recovered.
My brother, the nurse.
I want to thank you
for what you did.
Lenara means a lot to me.
To both of us.
Yes.
I'll leave you two alone.
Risian perfume.
Do they know what happened
to the wormhole yet?
Our best guess is
that the tetryon field
reacted to the probe's
shielding, producing a massive
graviton wave.
The important
thing is
no one got killed
and we brought the ship back
in one piece.
Oh, the ship--
how badly was it damaged?
Chief O'Brien says
he'll have it
good as new in two weeks.
Now stop
torturing yourself.
It wasn't your fault.
It was my project, my theories.
And you
shouldn't forget
that your project
and your theories
produced the first
artificially created
wormhole in history.
It's a huge
achievement.
You're right.
I am being
a little self-indulgent,
aren't I?
Yes, you are.
Well, I guess I'll have
a lot of work to do
when I get back to Trill.
Analyzing the telemetry
from the probe alone
will probably take months.
Probably.
Why not do the work
here with me?
With you.
The two of us together, you know
what that would mean.
I know exactly
what that would mean...
but I think
it's worth the price.
That's funny.
Bejal just spent
the last half hour
trying to convince me
that it wouldn't be worth it.
He wants me to go back to Trill
with him, tomorrow...
try to forget about you.
Well, at least he's consistent.
Don't be too hard on him.
He's only trying to look out
for his big sister.
Everyone is trying
to look out for us...
protect us from ourselves.
But in the end...
all that matters is how we feel
and what we
do about it,
because
either way,
we're the ones who have to live
with the consequences.
That's the tricky part, though,
isn't it?
Living with
the consequences.
When you're not with me,
when you're not around...
it's like a part of me
is missing.
I want to be with you
more than anything,
but I don't think
that I can do this.
Dax, I am not like you.
I don't have
a little Curzon inside me
telling me to be impulsive,
to ignore the rules,
to give up everything
that I've worked for.
Can you really walk away
from me?
From us?
After all this time,
we're together.
Don't throw that away.
I don't want to!
Maybe I need more time.
Maybe if I go back to Trill
for a while,
I-I'll think it over. I...
I can always come back later.
I wish I could believe you.
But ultimately it
comes down to this--
if you feel about me
the way I feel about you,
you won't go on that
transport tomorrow,
and if you do leave,
I think we both know...
you're never coming back again.
Good-bye, Commander.
Thank you.