Captain's Log, Stardate 49263.5.
At the request of
the Karemma Commerce Ministry
we've brought the Defiant
to a remote system
in the Gamma Quadrant
to discuss problems
that have surfaced
regarding
our recent trade agreement.
When we first agreed to use
Ferengi as intermediaries
we did it because
we knew the Dominion
would never tolerate
direct trade
between us and the Federation.
And we're glad to be of service
and I'm happy to say that
not a single Ferengi vessel
has been stopped
by the Jem'Hadar.
Unfortunately, we have found
there is very little profit
in doing business
with the Federation.
In order to comply
with all your commerce laws
we have had to pay
a series of taxes and fees
that have made
the costs too high.
What sort of taxes and fees
are you referring to?
For example
on a recent shipment
of Karemman fleece
a four percent surcharge
was added
to inspect the cargo
for changeling infiltrators.
What?!
You never know
where they might be hiding.
And a six percent tariff
was imposed
to help offset the lost income
of Tarkalian sheepherders.
Hardworking people.
You have to feel for them.
Need I go on, Captain?
No.
I think you've made your point.
These are the results
of the last weapons drill, sir.
These response times
are unacceptable, Ensign.
They are a little high, sir
but not if you take
into account that...
I want these response times
reduced by 15 percent.
Schedule another drill.
Yes, sir.
Want one?
I'm fasting.
Today is Ha'mara.
Ha'mara?
It's the anniversary
of the Emissary's arrival.
We fast to show our gratitude
to the Prophets
for sending him to us.
Last night, there was a festival
of lights in the capital.
Sounds beautiful.
Sorry we missed it.
Something tells me
the Captain scheduled
these negotiations
so he wouldn't have to attend.
Benjamin's never been one
for ceremonies
especially where
he's the center of attention.
Oh, I understand
how the Captain feels.
Still, it would have meant a lot
if the Emissary had been there.
After being stuck
in the Mess Hall all morning
with Quark and Hanok,
I'll bet he wishes he had gone.
Two ships have just entered
sensor range.
They're Jem'Hadar warships.
Red Alert.
Captain Sisko to the Bridge.
All hands, battle stations.
The Jem'Hadar are powering
up their weapons systems.
They are targeting
the Karemma ship.
They're here to punish us
for meeting with you.
If I give myself up
and assume full responsibility,
they may spare my ship.
I'm not about
to turn you over to them.
Open a channel.
This is Captain Benjamin Sisko
of the USS Defiant.
Stand down,
or we'll be forced to...
Return fire!
The Karemma ship
is coming about.
They're moving away, Captain.
Tell your people
to hold position.
We can't protect them
if they run.
The Karemma aren't responding
to our hails.
The Jem'Hadar
are changing course.
They're going
after the Karemma ship.
Move to intercept.
What are they doing?
They're hoping
that the Jem'Hadar
won't follow them
into the atmosphere.
They'd be smart not to.
That's a Class-J gas giant.
I'm reading wind speeds
of over 10,000
kilometers per hour.
23 of my people are on that ship
and they're going to die
because I was foolish enough
to defy the Dominion.
They're not going to die,
Minister.
Not if I can help it.
Sisko to O'Brien.
Go ahead, sir.
I'm taking the ship
into the atmosphere.
I know she wasn't
built for it, but I think
the ship can handle it.
Aye, sir.
I'll see if we can get
more power
to the structural
integrity field.
Adjusting shield geometry
for atmospheric entry.
Transferring auxiliary power
to the forward shields.
Take us in.
Five seconds to atmosphere.
There is so much interference
our imaging systems
are practically useless.
We've hit a crosscurrent.
Head into it.
We've slipped between
two thermal layers.
Wind velocities are
a little more manageable here.
Hold this altitude.
Any sign of the Karemma
or the Jem'Hadar?
No, but sensor range
is less than two kilometers.
There might be a way
we can increase it.
Let's do it.
Mr. Hanok, I think it'd be best
if you returned
to the Mess Hall.
As you wish, Captain.
Mr. Worf.
Sir.
What's the status
of our weapons systems?
The cloak is not effective
in this atmosphere
and the interference will jam
our torpedo guidance systems.
What about phasers?
We'll have to target them
manually.
Benjamin, we have an idea.
It's a little trick I learned
during the occupation.
Sometimes we'd evade
the Cardassian ships
by hiding in the Badlands.
Sensor range was limited,
so we learned to use
an active scan system
to navigate.
It works by echo location.
We send out a modulated
tetryon pulse
and if it reflects
off the hull of a ship
we can approximate its location.
But won't these pulses give away
our position as well?
We'd have to alter course
and speed after every one.
Good news, Minister.
Really?
I think I found the problem.
I made the mistake
of letting my brother Rom
execute these contracts.
Your brother?
Yes.
I'm ashamed to say it,
but he's an idiot.
You see, the Federation
and the Karemma
have very different laws
governing commerce
and I think poor Rom
must have gotten confused
by all the legalism.
Now, I will be
more than willing
to make up any losses
you might have encountered.
In fact, I will pay them back
with interest.
You cheated me, Quark,
and you haven't
even got the courage
to admit it.
If we survive this
I'll see that you never work
in the Gamma Quadrant again.
Nothing within
10,000 kilometers.
Ahead at one-quarter impulse.
Try again, Major.
There's something
400 kilometers below us.
It could be the Karemma.
I can't tell at this range.
Close to ten kilometers.
We're crossing into
another thermal layer.
Holding position
at ten kilometers.
Major?
From the size of it,
I'd say it's the Karemma.
I'm picking up two more ships.
Shields at 60 percent.
Return fire!
The Jem'Hadar
are breaking off their attack.
Are they going
after the Karemma?
I don't think
they've spotted them.
Captain, impulse
power is off line.
We're losing altitude.
Try using thrusters
to stabilize.
It's no use.
Hull pressure at two million GSC
and rising.
Sisko to Engine Room.
We need impulse power.
The primary ODN lines
have overloaded, Captain.
It'll be a few minutes.
Chief, if you can spare someone
to meet me in Jefferies tube 4
I'll try to reroute the power
through the secondary couplings.
Muniz, you go.
Yes, sir.
Hull pressure at nine million
GSC and still rising.
If we keep losing
altitude at this rate
the hull will collapse
in less than six minutes.
Sir, the phaser couplings were
overloaded during the attack.
It'll take at least two hours
to repair them.
Well, the Jem'Hadar
aren't going to let us
tractor the Karemma out of here
without a fight.
Right now, it seems
like we're the ones
who need to be
tractored out of here.
One thing at a time, Major.
Sisko to O'Brien.
O'Brien here.
How many atmospheric probes
do we have on board?
Two.
Could they be rigged
with warheads
from quantum torpedoes?
Well, we'd have to pull
the imaging systems out
to make room
in the casings, but...
I don't see why not.
How long?
20 minutes.
You've got ten.
You okay?
I'm all right.
The Captain's gotten us out
of tougher spots than this.
Last year, when the Romulans
tried to invade
the Founders' homeworld
we went up against
a dozen Jem'Hadar ships.
I know, Chief,
uh, you've told me the story.
Oh, yeah? Well, unless you
want to hear it again
you better get down
to the torpedo bay
and start working
on those probes.
I'm going.
Janklow.
I'm going to need
a dualitic inverter.
There's one in the cargo bay.
Right, Chief.
Hull breach on deck two.
An emergency force field
is in place
but it won't hold up long
against this pressure.
How many people are down there?
Half a dozen in Sick Bay.
Dax and Muniz
in Jefferies tube 4.
We've got to get them
out of there.
If we don't seal off
that deck now
we'll lose the entire ship.
Easy now.
Sisko to Bashir.
Go ahead.
The emergency force field
won't hold much longer.
We've got to evacuate that deck,
so we can seal it off.
Aye, sir.
Let's get everybody
past that bulkhead.
Dax, are you finished?
Not quite.
Get out of there
as soon as you're done.
In about 30 seconds, we're going
to have to seal that deck.
Bashir to Bridge.
I'm sealing the bulkhead now.
Dax!
Hurry!
Jadzia!
The force field is down.
Doctor, close that bulkhead.
But Jadzia's still in there!
Now, Doctor.
That's an order.
Julian...
Bridge.
She did it.
Helm.
Take us to a higher altitude.
O'Brien to Bridge.
One of the atmospheric probes
is armed and standing by.
We'll have the second one ready
in a few minutes.
Very good, Chief.
All right, Major.
Now that we've got something
to defend ourselves with
let's start looking
for the Karemma.
We're gaining altitude.
How can you tell?
Oh, I've got the lobes.
You've got them, too.
It's an old Ferengi expression.
Usually when we say
that someone has the lobes
we mean that they have
a keen business sense.
That's you.
I'll admit it...
you had me fooled.
I thought you were
just another easy mark
but you saw right
through my little scam
and taught me a thing or two
about doing business
in the Gamma Quadrant.
I guess I've gotten lazy.
I'm used to dealing
with the Federation.
If you thought
I was cheating you...
oh, you have no idea
what I was doing to them
and they still
haven't caught on.
If someone like me
could put one over on them
think what someone
like you could do.
Someone with my... lobes?
Exactly.
And I'm just the man
to help you do it.
We could become rich.
Rich beyond our dreams.
You...
are despicable.
I hate the Gamma Quadrant.
Sir, I have something.
It's a Jem'Hadar ship.
Just one?
They must have split up
to search for the Karemma.
It's about 70 kilometers
above us
on a roughly
perpendicular course.
Helm.
Come about
to course 075, mark 4.
Let's fall in behind them.
You think they detected us?
I don't know, but let's make it
harder for them.
Shut down
all nonessential systems.
It'll minimize
our power signature.
All stop.
Program the probe to home in
on the first metallic signature
it finds.
Sir.
If it does not locate anything
within 50 kilometers
the probe might turn back
and home in on the Defiant.
What if they changed course
or moved out of range?
Something tells me they may be
closer than you think.
The probe is ready, sir.
Fire.
O'Brien to Bridge.
Try the com panel.
Engine Room to Bridge.
Bridge, please respond.
Save your breath.
I don't think there's anybody
left alive up there.
Are you all right?
I think so.
Captain.
Computer, lights.
Bridge to Engine Room.
Boyce and Peterson are dead,
sir.
Try not to move.
You took a bad blow.
Get me a medkit.
Bridge systems
are completely off line.
We're not getting any power
to these consoles.
There.
The bleeding's stopped.
He's got a concussion.
Subcranial bleeding...
We need a medic.
The com system's down.
I'll go below
and try and find one.
It's stuck.
We will have to force it open.
I'm afraid
if he loses consciousness
he may slip into a coma
but I don't think I can risk
using a stimulant on him.
You have to keep him awake.
Talk to him.
Give him something to focus on.
All right.
I will attempt
to reach the Engine Room
and take over the ship
from there.
Good luck.
Captain.
Everything's going
to be all right
but you have to try
and stay awake for me.
I'm just going to keep talking,
all right?
But you have to listen.
It's very important
that you listen to me
beca... because there's
going to be a test later.
How do you feel?
Terrible.
That's not surprising
considering you took in
a few lungfuls of fluorine.
Remind me to hold
my breath next time.
I take it we're stuck in here?
I thought of trying to climb
up the turbolift shaft
but it flooded with gas.
I've had enough fluorine
for one day.
Maybe we should just stay put
and wait for someone
to come get us.
They probably don't even know
we're in here.
Our com signals can't cut
through the interference.
Is there anything else
I should know?
We only have a few hours
of breathable air.
Thanks, anyway...
for trying to rescue me.
A lot of good it did you.
I mean it.
It's funny.
A year ago, if you'd done
something like this
I would have thought you were
just trying to be a hero.
And now?
Now that I know you better...
I realize it was just
a really stupid thing to do.
Ah, you're welcome.
You're taking this
too personally.
Okay, I cheated you.
I cheat everyone.
It's business.
You see what you
can get away with
and you got to figure
the other guy's doing
the same to you.
That's not the way
the Karemma conduct business.
Oh, come on.
You can't tell me
you never padded an inventory
or pawned off a load
of substandard merchandise?
No, I haven't.
The Karemma believe
that merchandise has a set value
determined by the raw materials
and the labor
involved in creating it.
Factor in transportation costs
and a reasonable profit margin
and you arrive at a fair price.
You make it sound
so antiseptic.
Where's the bargaining?
Where's the scheming?
Where's the greed?
Greed leads to misjudgment
and that can result
in a loss of profits.
If there's no risk,
there's no thrill!
Your way is just barter.
If you want to win big
you got to be willing
to play the odds.
It's like gambling!
Gambling is the last
recourse of the desperate.
Only a fool would risk losing
what he has to chance.
Bah!
Commander,
am I glad to see you.
The Captain is injured
and all Bridge functions
are off line.
We're trying to route
command functions
to these consoles.
All right. I will
take command from here.
Who configured
these helm controls?
I did, sir.
They are not laid out properly.
I realize they're not
the same as on the Bridge
but I had to make
some changes, because...
I need to be able
to ascertain our
status at a glance.
Reconfigure these controls
to their standard layout.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Stevens, you will operate
the echo-location system
we've been using
to track the Jem'Hadar.
I'll do my best.
I expect nothing less.
Let's get to work.
So, I, ah, I was thinking
that we could go
on a four-shift rotation
because that would give people
a little more flexibility
with their time.
Th-There is a down side,
because that would mean
that every shift would have...
What am I doing?
I'm supposed to keep you awake,
not bore you to tears.
I'm sorry.
I don't know why
this is so hard for me.
I...
All I have to do is talk to you.
I mean, what do we
usually talk about?
We... talk about...
work.
You're right.
That is
what we usually talk about...
even when we're not working.
I get the feeling
it's not that way
between you and Dax, or...
you and Chief O'Brien
but then you're not a revered
figure in their religions.
I know.
You don't like it when I talk
about you as the Emissary.
That's how I think of you.
And maybe that's why
sometimes...
it's hard for me
to relax around you.
Nerys...
Y-yes, sir.
Tell me a story.
All right.
All right. Um...
Um, do you know the one
about the three brothers
who go to Jo'kala?
No.
Uh, they, um,
they were kava farmers
and one day,
they go into their field
and they see
the biggest kava root
that, uh, they've ever seen.
It's as big as a house.
"Well, that's going to make
us rich," says the oldest.
So, they decide
to sell it in the city.
Sir, I have something.
They're too small to be ships.
They're closing fast.
Torpedoes!
Hard a-port.
I'm modulating the deflectors.
It might confuse
their guidance systems.
Second one's still closing.
Range 100 meters.
Seventy-five...
Fifty...
Wha?
I suggest we leave
this room immediately.
And go where?
If that thing explodes
the entire ship
will be destroyed.
No. Maybe we should try
and diffuse it.
I think we should wait for help.
All right, but what if no one
can get to us?
I don't like the sound of that.
It's up to us.
Ah, there must be
an emergency tool kit
around here somewhere.
There.
The arming mechanism
must be somewhere in here.
I'm going to have
to remove this casing.
How?
There's no lock
that can't be picked.
Looks like the torpedo
hit somewhere in here.
Problem is, we're cut off
from that part of the ship.
Mm-hmm.
But we'll have
to think of something.
Mr. Stevens, recalibrate
the structural integrity field
to minimize the strain
caused by the torpedo.
The field generators are
already at their limits
compensating for the hull breach
on deck two.
I am aware of the situation.
If you cannot
carry out my orders
I will find someone who can.
That won't be necessary, sir.
Can I have a word with you, sir?
Of course.
With all due respect
I think you're riding
the men a bit hard.
You have to understand,
they're out of their element.
They're not Bridge officers.
They haven't been
to Starfleet Academy.
They're engineers.
They're used to being
given a problem to solve
and then going out
and figuring out how to do it.
What are you suggesting?
Well, give them a little slack.
Ease up on the reins.
Let them do what they're good at
and give them a little
encouragement now and then.
I will take it
under consideration.
I'm so cold.
These walls aren't
that well insulated.
It's going to get even colder.
Come here.
Better?
What?
Just remembering something.
Tell me.
When I first got to the station,
I used to have this fantasy
that you and I went off
on a runabout together
on some mission.
Something went wrong
with the ship
and we ended up
drifting around for a few days
until they sent someone
to rescue us.
If you don't mind
my saying, Julian
that's a very strange fantasy.
It seemed the only way
that you and I could spend
any time alone together.
You were always avoiding me.
Oh, it's just that...
you came on so strong.
You never really
gave me a chance
to get to know you.
Well, you're right.
I didn't.
Well, don't worry, Jadzia.
It's been a long time
since I had
that particular fantasy.
Oh?
You sound disappointed.
Julian!
That's right.
You enjoyed being chased
and now you miss it.
That's preposterous
and if you start
chasing after me again...
Oh, don't worry, Jadzia.
Now I know you liked it,
I don't need to, do I?
I require your assistance.
I need a weapon.
We still have
one atmospheric probe.
No, if my plan is going to work,
the probe will not be available.
I need something else.
The phasers are
out of the question.
The emitters
are completely fused.
But the phaser generator's
working fine.
The deflector array.
With a few modifications
we could use it
as a phaser emitter.
It might not be
what you have in mind, sir.
And there is one problem.
It will overload
after the first shot.
I only need one shot.
How long will it take you
to make the modifications?
20 minutes?
Ten if we bypass the safeties.
Proceed.
I think we should route
the generator output
through the secondary
power grid.
We'll have to recalibrate
the ODN manifold.
That'll overload
the whole system.
What a mess.
Ah, we'll worry
about that tomorrow.
Yeah, that's easy
for you to say.
It's your day off.
Don't count on it.
...so the three brothers
started arguing
about how to divide the money
for the kava root.
The oldest said
that, uh, he should get more
because it was his idea
to sell it in the city
and the youngest objected
saying he was the one
to till the...
This can't happen!
You can't die!
You're the Emissary.
There's still so much
for you to do.
I don't know if this is
the right thing to do or not
but I'm going to give
you a stimulant.
Captain...
I know my beliefs
make you uncomfortable
around me sometimes
and... maybe that's why
you keep me at arm's length.
But I don't care
about that right now
and I am going to pray
because I don't know
what else to do.
I'm losing you
and I can't let that happen.
Jia'kaja
tre'nu'tol'a rem...
La'por i'lanu kos...
I'nar tan'a'tali nor...
Everything's ready, sir.
We can target
the deflector from here.
Good work.
Take your posts.
Mr. O'Brien.
Nothing within
scanning range, sir.
The Jem'Hadar are out there.
You can be certain of that.
Gently!
All right.
Now... what?
One of these diodes
connects the warhead
to the power source.
The other one
is the firing mechanism.
How do you know that?
I saw a design schematic once.
Where?
At the Ministry of Trade
on Karemma.
We sell these torpedoes
to the Jem'Hadar.
I thought you said
you never sold
substandard merchandise?
This was supposed
to explode on impact, wasn't it?
Maybe I should
offer them a refund.
We'd better do something
about this torpedo of yours.
We have to remove
the firing diode...
only I don't know
which one it is.
And if we pick the wrong one
we die!
Oh... it's not funny.
We just have
to pick the right one.
It's fifty-fifty.
Better odds than you get
at the dabo table.
Dabo?
Yes. It's a game.
If we get out of this,
I'll teach it to you.
Choose one.
How?
It's a gamble.
Go with your instincts.
You're thinking too much.
You just have to reach in and...
pick one!
Ooh! Oh, oh.
I think we have a winner.
That was... exciting.
Feels good, doesn't it?
Yes!
That's how it works.
The bigger the risk,
the bigger the win.
Yes.
You know...
there's another risk
you could take.
Staying in business with me.
You never give up, do you?
No.
I tried to cheat you and I lost
but that doesn't mean
I'm going to give up the game.
Come on, Hanok.
What do you say?
You want to keep playing?
Let's talk about those
Bolian currency fluctuations.
Jia'kaja, tre'nu'tol'a rem...
La'por i'lanu kos...
I'nar.
Jia'kaja, tre'...
Major...
Yes, Captain?
What happened?
The Jem'Hadar hit us pretty bad
and Worf went down
to the Engine Room...
No, no, no.
What happened
to the three brothers?
They... gave all the money away
and went back
to the farm where they belonged.
It's good.
Major...
Sir?
Tell me another story.
I'd love to, sir.
I've got something, sir.
It's the Jem'Hadar.
They've locked on
to the tetryon pulse.
Stand by, Mr. Stevens.
Now.
What do you say
we find the Karemma
and get out of here?
Defiant Log, supplemental.
Damage control teams are
repairing the ship's systems
and medics are tending
to injured crew members.
We have located the Karemma
ship deep in the atmosphere
and are moving to assist.
It appears that it
will have to be abandoned
and its crew brought back
to Deep Space 9
until transportation
can be arranged
to the Karemma homeworld.
It's going to be a levy.
- A levy?
- A levy.
Where do you?
I don't see any levy.
Right here.
Put the levy right there.
Oh!
Pass five.
Too bad... you lose
half your stake.
You can either quit now or...
try to double it.
My advice is to take
what latinum you have left
and walk away.
Just because one loses a bet
doesn't mean
one gives up the game.
Exactly.
May I suggest
placing your next wager
on double down.
Put it all on triple over.
Oh, I think
that's a big mistake.
Triple over.
Nothing personal, Quark.
Of course not.
Dabo!
You're really catching on.
Ah!
17 brothers and sisters.
Well, now...
that's quite a family.
Excuse me, Morn.
It's your turn.
For what?
Darts.
That's right.
I'm sorry, Morn.
It's been, uh...
nice talking to you.
Thank you for rescuing me.
Now we're even.
Excuse me, sir.
Here's the repair schedule
we drew up for the Defiant.
With your approval
we thought we'd start
by tearing out the ODN lines.
They're shot.
It'd be easier to get
to the manifolds
that way, and then we figured...
Proceed at your own discretion,
Mr. Stevens.
Thank you, sir.
How long will the repairs take?
16 hours.
Oh, you can do it in 12.
12... sure.
No problem.
See?
You can give them a little slack
but you can't take
your hands off the reins.
The Karemma transport
will be here at 1800 tomorrow
and the Defiant should be ready
to escort them back
to the Gamma Quadrant.
Good.
Major...
it occurred to me
that we might consider
going to a four-shift rotation.
I think the crew might
appreciate more flexibility
in their schedules.
I'll look into it
first thing in the morning.
Major...
what are you doing
for the next few hours?
Well, I'm... going off duty,
so I thought I'd just relax.
Would you like to go
to a baseball game?
I'd love to, sir.
Good.
Meet me at Holosuite 3
in half an hour.
I'll... I'll see you there.
Nerys...
You need one of those.
You can get
the hot dogs from Quark.
Hot dogs?
Oh, he'll know.