A LOT OF KICK FOR A '45 DOM.
THANK YOU, MISTER...?
MISTER..?
BASHIR.
JULIAN BASHIR.
( clapping continues )
WHO'S THAT?
AN UNINVITED GUEST.
EXCUSE ME.
NICE TUX.
THANK YOU.
NOW...
GET OUT.
BUT, DOCTOR, I'VE
ONLY JUST ARRIVED.
BREAKING INTO A HOLOSUITE
DURING SOMEONE'S PROGRAM
IS NOT ONLY RUDE,
IT'S ILLEGAL.
I SHOULD CALL ODO
AND HAVE YOU ARRESTED.
WHAT AN EXTREME REACTION
THAT WOULD BE.
YOU MUST BE VERY EMBARRASSED
BY THIS PROGRAM.
I'M NOT EMBARRASSED.
I'M ANNOYED THAT YOU HAVE
INTRUDED INTO MY PRIVACY.
OH, PRIVACY, INDEED.
I THINK IT GOES FAR DEEPER
THAN THAT, DOCTOR.
EVER SINCE YOU'VE RECEIVED
THIS NEW PROGRAM,
YOU'VE SPENT VIRTUALLY
EVERY FREE HOUR
IN THE HOLOSUITE.
BUT YOU HAVEN'T TOLD ANYONE
WHAT THE PROGRAM IS.
AM I SUPPOSED TO?
NO, NO. NO.
BUT YOU'RE SUCH A...
FORGIVE ME--
A TALKATIVE MAN,
AND IT'S SO UNUSUAL
FOR YOU TO HAVE SECRETS.
I MUST HAVE PICKED UP
THAT HABIT FROM YOU.
NOW, IF YOU WILL EXCUSE ME.
IS THIS FANTASY OF YOURS...
TRULY REVEALING
OF YOUR INNER PSYCHE?
WHAT?
IS THAT WHY YOU'RE
SO PROTECTIVE?
ARE YOU AFRAID
THAT I'LL FIND OUT
SOME HUMILIATING SECRETS
OF THE REAL JULIAN BASHIR?
THIS IS A FANTASY.
I'M NOT HIDING ANYTHING.
WELL, IF YOU'VE
NOTHING TO HIDE,
THEN WHY NOT LET ME STAY?
ALL RIGHT.
AH.
Bashir:
NOW, I HAVE
TO BE AT WORK
IN TWO HOURS, AND I'D LIKE
TO ENJOY MYSELF.
SO KEEP QUIET
AND DON'T RAIN
ON MY PARADE.
PARADE?!
NEVER MIND.
DON'T WORRY, DOCTOR.
I CAN BE VERY
DISCREET.
YOU'LL BARELY
KNOW I'M HERE.
GOOD.
BUT IF I MAY MAKE
ONE OBSERVATION...
GARAK...
I ONLY WANT TO POINT OUT
THAT YOUR LOVELY
COMPANION IS LEAVING.
ODD. SHE SEEMED
SO INTERESTED
IN YOUR ADVANCES
JUST A MOMENT AGO.
I WONDER WHAT
SCARED HER AWAY.
OH, NO.
I DO APOLOGIZE.
YOU MUST BE INCENSED.
IN FACT, IF I WERE
IN YOUR SHOES
I'D GRAB A BOTTLE
OF CHAMPAGNE
AND SHOOT ME.
I CAN SEE I'M GOING
TO REGRET THIS.
DON'T WORRY, DOCTOR.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
A WONDERFUL TIME.
AFTER ALL, WHAT COULD
POSSIBLY GO WRONG?
YOU LIVE HERE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
DECORATE IT
YOURSELF?
THE DECOR IS APPROPRIATE
FOR THE PERIOD-- 1964.
HOW DID YOU PRONOUNCE
THE NAME OF THIS CITY?
KOWLOON.
IT'S PART OF HONG KONG.
AND THE NIGHTCLUB WAS IN PARIS,
WHICH, IF I REMEMBER CORRECTLY,
WAS ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE PLANET.
MR. BASHIR,
I DIDN'T EXPECT
YOU HOME SO SOON.
I DECIDED TO LEAVE PARIS
A LITTLE EARLY.
ALLOW ME TO INTRODUCE
MY FRIEND, MR. GARAK.
GARAK, THIS IS
MY PERSONAL VALET, MONA LUVSITT.
PLEASED TO MAKE
YOUR ACQUAINTANCE.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO CHANGE
INTO SOMETHING MORE COMFORTABLE?
OH, THAT WOULD BE PERFECT.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN FIND
MR. GARAK SOMETHING
AS WELL.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO PUT THIS AWAY?
PLEASE.
CARE FOR A DRINK?
NOT JUST YET.
IS SHE YOUR VALET
OR YOUR PERSONAL ASSASSIN?
VALET.
MONA'S VERY CAPABLE.
SHE SPEAKS SEVEN LANGUAGES,
HAS DEGREES IN BIOLOGY
AND CHEMISTRY
AND PHYSICS,
CAN FLY ANYTHING
FROM A JET
TO A HELICOPTER,
AND MAKES
AN EXCELLENT MARTINI.
CHEERS.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
I TAKE IT
YOUR CHARACTER
IS SOME KIND
OF RICH DILETTANTE
WITH A FASCINATION
FOR WOMEN AND WEAPONS.
ACTUALLY, MY CHARACTER
IS FAR MORE DISREPUTABLE.
I'M A SPY.
A SPY?
AND YOU LIVE HERE?
YES. I WORK FOR ONE
OF THE NATION-STATES
OF THIS ERA,
GREAT BRITAIN
WHICH IS BATTLING
VARIOUS OTHER NATIONS
IN WHAT IS CALLED
THE "COLD WAR."
THIS APARTMENT, MY CLOTHES,
WEAPONS, EVEN MY VALET,
WERE PROVIDED TO ME
BY MY GOVERNMENT.
I THINK I JOINED
THE WRONG INTELLIGENCE SERVICE.
Sisko:
ORINOCO TO
DEEP SPACE NINE.
THIS IS CAPTAIN SISKO
REQUESTING LANDING CLEARANCE.
Welcome back, Captain.
YOU'RE CLEAR TO SET DOWN
ON LANDING PAD 3.
HOW WAS THE CONFERENCE?
INFORMATIVE, BUT I'VE GOT
A SHIPLOAD
OF TIRED OFFICERS HERE.
I THINK WE'LL BE HAPPY
TO BE IN OUR OWN BEDS TONIGHT.
I can imagine.
THERE'S SOME MESSAGE TRAFFIC
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND
FOR YOU TO LOOK AT...
CAPTAIN, THERE'S SOME KIND
OF POWER SURGE IN THE WARP CORE.
LOOKS LIKE A FLUCTUATION
IN THE PLASMA COILS.
WE BETTER TAKE THE WARP CORE
OFF-LINE.
I CAN'T. THERE'S SOMETHING
WRONG WITH THE COMMAND
CONTROL SYSTEMS;
I'M COMPLETELY LOCKED OUT.
MAGNETIC INTERLOCKS
ARE FAILING.
WARP CORE BREACH
IS IMMINENT.
EJECT THE WARP CORE.
THE EJECTION SYSTEM
ISN'T RESPONDING.
CORRECTION:
THE EJECTION SYSTEM IS MISSING.
WE'VE BEEN SABOTAGED.
TEN SECONDS
TO WARP CORE BREACH.
ORINOCO, CUT YOUR IMPULSE
ENGINES AND DROP YOUR
DEFLECTORS.
WE'RE GOING TO BEAM YOU
OUT OF THERE.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
CUT MAIN POWER.
I'VE LOCKED ON. ENERGIZING.
Odo:
WHAT HAPPENED?
CAPTAIN SISKO'S
RUNABOUT
EXPLODED WHILE I WAS
TRYING TO BEAM THEM BACK.
SOME ENERGY TRAVELED BACK
ALONG THE TRANSPORTER BEAM
AND BLEW UP THE PRIMARY
ENERGIZING COILS.
DO STILL WE HAVE
THEIR PATTERNS?
YES. THEY'RE IN THE BUFFER,
BUT THE PATTERNS
WILL START TO DEGRADE
IF NOT USED IMMEDIATELY.
WE NEED TO STORE
THE PATTERNS SOMEWHERE.
THIS IS MORE COMPLICATED
THAN JUST AN ORDINARY
TRANSPORTER PATTERN.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO PRESERVE
ALL THE NEURAL SIGNATURES
OF EVERYONE ON THAT RUNABOUT.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MUCH MEMORY
IT WOULD TAKE
TO SAVE JUST ONE PERSON'S
NEURAL SIGNATURE,
MUCH LESS FIVE?
I DON'T THINK WE HAVE
ANY CHOICE.
COMPUTER, I NEED TO STORE ALL
DATA CURRENTLY IN
THE TRANSPORTER PATTERN BUFFER
WHERE CAN I SAVE IT?
There is insufficient computer
memory to save the data.
PATTERN BUFFERS BEGINNING TO
LOSE COHERENCE.
THE PATTERNS WILL START TO
DEGRADE ANY SECOND NOW.
COMPUTER, WHAT IF WE WIPED
ALL COMPUTER MEMORY IN
EVERY SYSTEM ON THE STATION,
AND THEN STORE THE PATTERNS?
That procedure has not been
tested. It cannot be predicted.
THE BUFFER IS DEPOLARIZING.
COMPUTER, THIS IS A COMMAND
PRIORITY OVERRIDE.
WIPE ALL COMPUTER MEMORY
NECESSARY IN ORDER TO SAVE
THE PATTERNS FROM THE BUFFER.
AUTHORIZATION EDDINGTON,
065 ALPHA ENABLED.
Executing command override.
TRICORDER.
THE BUFFER'S LOST COHERENCE.
THE PATTERNS ARE GONE.
DID THE COMPUTER SAVE THEM
IN TIME?
I THINK SO,
BUT I'M NOT SURE WHERE.
THANK YOU, MY DEAR.
YES, THIS SHOULD
DO NICELY.
ALTHOUGH I'M NOT TOO
SURE ABOUT THE COLLAR.
IT'S PERFECT.
HUH?
I'LL HAVE THESE CLEANED
RIGHT AWAY.
THANK YOU.
ISN'T THIS A RATHER
OSTENTATIOUS LIFE FOR A SPY?
IT'S ALL PART
OF MY COVER.
I'M POSING AS
A WEALTHY JET-SETTER,
SO I HAVE TO ACT
LIKE ONE.
JET-SETTER?
PEOPLE OF THIS ERA
USED TO TRAVEL IN...
( pounding )
( with Russian accent ):
JULIAN.
I MUST HAVE FALLEN ASLEEP.
VERY FUNNY.
WHO ELSE DID YOU INVITE
ALONG WITH YOU TODAY?
WELL, THIS WASN'T
MY IDEA.
MAJOR?
COLONEL, ACTUALLY.
COLONEL ANASTASIA KOMANANOV,
K.G.B.
OH, JULIAN, I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D SEE YOU ALIVE AGAIN.
NOT AFTER YOU FELL OUT
OF THAT DIRIGIBLE OVER ICELAND.
I HAD A PARACHUTE,
AND THERE WAS A SUBMARINE THERE
WAITING FOR ME,
BUT HOW DID YOU
KNOW ABOUT THAT?
HAVE YOU BEEN DOWNLOADING
MY HOLOSUITE PROGRAM?
OH, JULIAN,
YOU ARE NOT WELL.
LET'S LIE DOWN.
Garak:
I MUST SAY
MAJOR KIRA'S CERTAINLY THROWING
HERSELF INTO THE ROLE, DOCTOR.
NERYS, PLEASE...
WHO IS THIS
MAJOR NERYS KIRA?
KIRA NERYS, ACTUALLY.
PERHAPS...
THIS ISN'T MAJOR KIRA AFTER ALL.
I'M BEGINNING
TO THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
COMPUTER, RESTORE
THE IMAGE
OF COLONEL KOMANANOV BACK
TO ITS ORIGINAL PARAMETERS.
Unable to comply.
The character parameters of
Colonel Komananov are correct.
I'D SAY SOMEONE'S
BEEN TAMPERING
WITH YOUR PROGRAM, DOCTOR.
JULIAN, WE DON'T
HAVE TIME FOR GAMES.
THERE IS MUCH TO TALK ABOUT.
EXCUSE ME.
COMPUTER,
FREEZE PROGRAM.
Unable to comply.
Computer control
has been disrupted
due to
a station-wide emergency.
EMERGENCY?
BASHIR TO OPS,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WE'VE GOT OUR HANDS FULL RIGHT
NOW, DOCTOR. STAND BY.
ODO, WAIT.
DOCTOR, WHERE ARE YOU
AND DO YOU HAVE ACCESS
TO A WORKING COMPUTER CONSOLE?
I'm in Holosuite 3.
THE PROGRAM IS RUNNING, BUT IT
WON'T COMPLY WITH MY COMMANDS.
THE PROGRAM IS
STILL RUNNING?
I DEMAND TO KNOW
WHO YOU ARE TALKING TO.
...Julian, tell me!
THAT SOUNDED LIKE KIRA.
Bashir:
Not exactly.
SOMEONE HAS REPLACED
ONE OF THE CHARACTERS
WITH THE IMAGE OF MAJOR KIRA.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
Stay where you are, Doctor.
KEEP THE PROGRAM RUNNING
FOR NOW.
WE'LL GET RIGHT BACK TO YOU.
JULIAN, TALK TO ME.
TELL ME WHAT IS HAPPENING.
I'M NOT SURE MYSELF.
Eddington:
Ops to Bashir.
DOCTOR, WHATEVER YOU DO,
DON'T END THAT PROGRAM.
WHY NOT?
There has been
a transporter accident.
WE BELIEVE THE HOLOSUITE
MEMORY CORE
IS HOLDING THE
TRANSPORTER PATTERNS
OF FIVE CREW MEMBERS.
IF YOU STOP THE PROGRAM
their patterns might be lost.
HOW COULD THAT HAPPEN?
It's a long story,
BUT AT THIS MOMENT, THE PATTERNS
OF CAPTAIN SISKO,
KIRA, WORF, DAX
AND O'BRIEN
EXIST ONLY IN THE
HOLOSUITE DATABASE.
DON'T LEAVE THE HOLOSUITE.
IF YOU DO, IT MIGHT DISRUPT
THE HOLO-IMAGING ARRAY,
AND RIGHT NOW
WE CAN'T TAKE ANY CHANCES.
YOU'LL HAVE TO STAY IN THERE
AND KEEP THE PROGRAM RUNNING
FOR NOW.
UNDERSTOOD.
We'll get back to you, Doctor.
OH, JULIAN...
YOU ARE SO TENSE.
IT'S BEEN ONE OF THOSE DAYS.
I WISH I COULD
RELAX YOU,
BUT I AM HERE
ON BUSINESS.
IN THE LAST 24 HOURS,
A SERIES OF EARTHQUAKES
HAVE STRUCK CITIES
FROM VLADIVOSTOK
TO NEW YORK.
OUR SEISMOLOGISTS HAVE ANALYZED
THE EARTHQUAKES,
AND HAVE COME
TO THE CONCLUSION
THAT THEY
ARE ARTIFICIAL.
SO? THAT'S NOT SO DIFFICULT.
ONE ONLY HAS TO...
GARAK.
YOUR FRIEND
SEEMS TO KNOW SOMETHING.
BELIEVE ME,
HE KNOWS NOTHING.
IF YOU SAY SO.
BECAUSE OF THE GLOBAL NATURE
OF THIS CRISIS,
MY GOVERNMENT AND YOURS
HAVE DECIDED TO COOPERATE.
WE WILL
BE WORKING...
VERY CLOSELY.
I'M SURE WE WILL.
OUR ASSIGNMENT
IS TO FIND OUT
WHO CAUSED
THE EARTHQUAKES
AND WHAT THEY WANT.
A RATHER VAGUE ASSIGNMENT.
WE DO HAVE ONE CLUE.
ONE OF THE WORLD'S
LEADING SEISMOLOGISTS,
PROFESSOR HONEY BARE,
HAS VANISHED.
WE BELIEVE... SHE
HAS BEEN KIDNAPPED.
I DIDN'T THINK
SHE WAS YOUR TYPE.
YOU SAID
SHE'S BEEN KIDNAPPED.
WE THINK SO.
SHE DISAPPEARED
ONLY A FEW HOURS
BEFORE THE FIRST QUAKE
STRUCK NEW YORK CITY.
DOCTOR, WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN EMERGENCY.
IS THIS REALLY THE TIME
TO BE PLAYING GAMES?
LOOK!
INTERESTING.
IF HONEY BARE IS KILLED,
THE COMPUTER
WILL ERASE HER CHARACTER
FROM ITS PROGRAM.
NOW SINCE THE PROGRAM THINKS
THAT DAX IS HONEY BARE...
THE COMPUTER WOULD ACTUALLY BE
ERASING COMMANDER DAX'S PATTERN.
KIRA... UH, ANA...
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHERE PROFESSOR BARE IS?
SHE WAS LAST SEEN...
I'LL BE RIGHT
WITH YOU, MONA.
CHIEF...
NO.
IT'S FALCON.
NICE TO SEE YOU, MR. BASHIR.
NOW I THINK WE HAVE
A LITTLE UNFINISHED BUSINESS.
SURPRISED TO SEE ME,
MR. BASHIR?
YOU COULD SAY THAT.
WELL, YOU SHOULD USE SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE LETHAL
THAN A CHAMPAGNE CORK.
SOMETHING...
LIKE THIS.
Kira:
WAIT.
WAIT, PLEASE.
LET US HAVE ONE LAST KISS.
WHY NOT?
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
A ROMANTIC AT HEART.
EARRING.
ALL RIGHT, BASHIR,
THAT'S ENOUGH.
( groaning )
INTERESTING JEWELRY.
I BOUGHT THOSE
FOR ANASTASIA LAST CHRISTMAS.
YOU'RE BLEEDING.
THE HOLOSUITE SAFETIES
MUST BE OFF.
TIME TO CLIP
THIS BIRD'S WINGS.
NO!
NYET. WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE CAN'T KILL HIM.
JULIAN, WHAT
ARE YOU SAYING?
HE'S BEEN TRYING TO KILL YOU
FOR NINE YEARS.
I WOULDN'T DISMISS HER IDEA
SO QUICKLY, DOCTOR.
BUT THAT'S MILES.
NO. AS YOU
POINTED OUT, HE'S FALCON--
A HIRED ASSASSIN
WHO'S GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING HE CAN
TO KILL YOU,
AND WITHOUT THE HOLOSUITE
SAFETIES IN PLACE,
HE MAY JUST DO THAT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO--
KILL HIM?
I WANT YOU TO STOP
TREATING THIS LIKE A GAME
WHERE EVERYTHING'S GOING TO
TURN OUT ALL RIGHT IN THE END.
REAL SPIES
HAVE TO MAKE HARD CHOICES.
YOU WANT TO SAVE DAX?
FINE, BUT YOU MAY NOT
HAVE THE LUXURY
OF SAVING EVERYONE.
WHO IS DAX?
EVENTUALLY,
YOU MAY HAVE
TO LET SOMEONE DIE.
I'LL DEAL WITH
THAT SITUATION
IF AND WHEN IT HAPPENS.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE HAVE TO FIND DAX.
WHO IS DAX?
ANNA, I PROMISE I'LL EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING LATER.
NOW, YOU SAID PROFESSOR BARE
HAD BEEN KIDNAPPED.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY SUSPECTS?
WE BELIEVE THAT DR. NOAH
IS BEHIND THE ABDUCTIONS.
DURING THE LAST TWO YEARS,
HE HAS KIDNAPPED
AN ELITE GROUP
OF 60 ARTISANS AND SCIENTISTS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
NO ONE KNOWS WHY
OR WHERE HE HAS TAKEN THEM,
BUT OUR SOURCES TELL US
THAT EACH OF THE MISSING PEOPLES
WAS INVITED TO MEET DR. NOAH
AT A CLUB IN PARIS
SHORTLY BEFORE
THEY DISAPPEARED.
THE CLUB INGÉNUE.
DA.
I HAD A FEELING.
SORRY, MY DEAR.
I HOPE YOU REMEMBER
HOW TO TIE A BOW TIE.
WE'RE GOING TO PARIS.
WHO IS DAX?!
I'VE HAD TO MAKE
A FEW MODIFICATIONS
TO THIS HOLOSUITE
OVER THE YEARS.
A FEW? IT'S LIKE A JUNKYARD
IN HERE.
MY BROTHER WON'T LET ME
BUY NEW COMPONENTS
SO I'VE HAD TO SCAVENGE
FOR WHAT I NEED.
I'M BARELY BREAKING EVEN
ON THE HOLOSUITES AS IT IS.
IF I HAD TO BUY NEW EQUIPMENT
EVERY TIME...
WHERE'S THE CORE
MEMORY INTERFACE?
OH... IT'S... RIGHT
BEHIND THE SPATULA.
THE SPATULA?
IT'S MADE OF A COPPER-
YTTERBIUM COMPOSITE--
THE PERFECT
PLASMA CONDUCTOR.
I FOUND THEM.
ALL FIVE OF THEIR PHYSICAL
PATTERNS ARE IN HERE...
AND THEY'RE STABLE.
WHY HERE?
THE HOLOSUITE
IS SPECIFICALLY DESIGNED
TO STORE
HIGHLY COMPLEX ENERGY PATTERNS.
THE COMPUTER'S PROCESSING
THEIR PHYSICAL PATTERNS
AS IF THEY WERE
HOLOSUITE CHARACTERS.
THE TROUBLE IS,
I'M NOT READING
ANY NEURAL ENERGY.
NEURAL ENERGY HAS TO BE STORED
AT THE QUANTUM LEVEL.
THE HOLOSUITE
CAN'T HANDLE THAT.
SO IF THEIR PHYSICAL BODIES
ARE STORED HERE,
WHERE ARE
THEIR BRAIN PATTERNS?
EVERYWHERE ELSE.
THEIR BRAIN PATTERNS
ARE SO LARGE
THAT THEY'RE TAKING UP
EVERY BIT OF COMPUTER MEMORY
ON THE STATION--
REPLICATOR MEMORY,
WEAPONS,
LIFE SUPPORTS.
HE MAY BE RIGHT.
SO WHAT DO WE DO
ABOUT IT?
HOW DO WE
GET THEM BACK?
♪ ♪
UH, I'D LIKE
TO SEE DR. NOAH.
I HAVE AN INVITATION.
MAY I SEE YOUR INVITATION?
DR. NOAH?
I AM DUCHAMPS.
I AM DR. NOAH'S...
ASSOCIATE.
MAY I?
MY NAME'S MERRIWEATHER--
PATRICK MERRIWEATHER,
AND THIS IS MY WIFE
ANASTASIA,
AND MY FRIEND, MR. GARAK.
CHARMED.
YOUR INVITATION,
MR. MERRIWEATHER.
I... DON'T HAVE ONE.
DR. NOAH DOES NOT LIKE
UNEXPECTED GUESTS.
OH, I BELIEVE DR. NOAH
WOULD BE VERY INTERESTED
IN MEETING MY HUSBAND.
HE'S ONE OF
THE LEADING GEOLOGISTS
IN THE WORLD.
NOW, WHY WOULD THAT
INTEREST DR. NOAH?
OH, WE BELIEVE HE'S TAKEN
QUITE AN INTEREST
IN THE SCIENCES.
AFTER ALL, HE HAS
INVITED SEVERAL
OF THE WORLD'S TOP SCIENTISTS
TO THIS... CLUB.
ISN'T THAT TRUE?
I MUST SAY,
I FEEL A LITTLE INSULTED
BY BEING LEFT OUT
OF SUCH AN ILLUSTRIOUS GROUP.
HOW UNFORTUNATE.
OF COURSE...
A MEETING STILL CAN BE ARRANGED
FOR A PRICE.
OH?
FIVE MILLION FRANCS.
NO PROBLEM.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHERE'S THE REST
OF YOUR MONEY?
RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
SHALL WE BEGIN?
Odo:
A CARDASSIAN
SEPARATIST GROUP
CALLING THEMSELVES
"THE TRUE WAY"
HAS CLAIMED
RESPONSIBILITY
FOR SABOTAGING
THE RUNABOUT.
EVER HEARD
OF THEM BEFORE?
MMM. THEY'RE OPPOSED
TO THE PEACE TREATY.
THEY BLAME THE FEDERATION
FOR CARDASSIA'S ECONOMIC
AND POLITICAL TROUBLES,
ET CETERA, ET CETERA.
UNTIL NOW, THEY'VE NEVER
COMMITTED ANY TERRORIST ACTIONS
TO SUPPORT THEIR BELIEFS.
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND?
FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL,
QUARK WAS RIGHT.
THE COMPUTER HAS STORED
THE NEURAL ENERGY PATTERNS
OF EVERYONE ON THE RUNABOUT
THROUGHOUT THE ENTIRE STATION.
DON'T EVERYONE
THANK ME AT ONCE.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO
IS REINTEGRATE
THEIR NEURAL PATTERNS
WITH THEIR PHYSICAL PATTERNS
FROM THE HOLOSUITE
AND RE-MATERIALIZE THEM.
Eddington:
I SAY WE USE THE DEFIANT.
ITS POWER SYSTEMS
AND COMPUTERS
ARE INDEPENDENT
OF THE STATION
AND IT HAS ITS
OWN TRANSPORTER.
SOUNDS GOOD, EXCEPT...
EXCEPT WHAT?
WELL, MY EQUIPMENT
ISN'T DESIGNED
TO INTERFACE WITH
STARFLEET SYSTEMS.
I MAY HAVE TO MAKE
SOME MODIFICATIONS.
CARD.
NINE.
FIVE MILLION FRANCS.
YOU'RE QUITE A BACCARAT PLAYER,
MR. MERRIWEATHER.
BACCARAT AND GEOLOGY
ARE MY LIFE.
NOW, MR. DUCHAMPS, I BELIEVE
I'VE MET YOUR CONDITIONS.
WHEN DO WE LEAVE?
RIGHT NOW.
( speaking Russian )
ANOTHER DECORATOR'S
NIGHTMARE.
THIS ERA HAD
A DISTINCT LACK OF TASTE.
WHERE ARE WE?
WELCOME TO PARADISE,
MR. MERRIWEATHER.
I BELIEVE
YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR ME.
MY NAME IS HIPPOCRATES NOAH.
MR. MERRIWEATHER...
I UNDERSTAND
YOUR FIELD IS GEOLOGY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN I AM SURE
YOU CAN APPRECIATE
THE STONES IN MY MOST
RECENT ACQUISITION.
A MOST STRIKING
DISPLAY...
OF RUBIES...
TOURMALINE...
SAPPHIRE... TOPAZ...
AND JUDGING BY THE HIGH CHROMIUM
CONTENT OF THE RUBIES,
I'D SAY THEY COME FROM
THE HYDROTHERMAL DEPOSITS
ON THE TIBETAN PLATEAU...
WHICH ISN'T SURPRISING
CONSIDERING WE'RE ON
THE SOUTHEASTERN SLOPE
OF MT. EVEREST AT ABOUT
22,000 FEET, I SHOULD SAY.
25, ACTUALLY.
YOU MUST NOT GET MANY TOURISTS.
MY GUESTS AND I
PLACE A PREMIUM ON OUR PRIVACY.
WE DON'T WANT
ANY UNWELCOME GUESTS,
SUCH AS MEN SENT BY GOVERNMENTS
WHO DISAGREE
WITH MY POLITICAL PHILOSOPHY.
AND WHAT IS YOUR PHILOSOPHY?
ARE YOU
SOME KIND OF ANARCHIST?
QUITE THE OPPOSITE.
I BELIEVE IN AN ORDERLY WORLD...
A FAR CRY FROM THE CHAOS
WE FIND OURSELVES IN TODAY.
WE ARE BUILDING
A NEW FUTURE HERE,
A NEW BEGINNING
FOR MANKIND.
A NEW CHAPTER
IN HUMAN HISTORY
WILL OPEN RIGHT HERE
ON MY ISLAND.
ISLAND?
FORGIVE ME.
SOMETIMES I DO
GET AHEAD OF MYSELF.
ALLOW ME TO EXPLAIN.
WE'RE ALMOST READY.
I PROGRAMMED
THE LASER SEQUENCE,
AND I'M MAKING SOME
LAST-MINUTE ADJUSTMENTS
TO THE SOUTH AMERICAN SITE.
I DO HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE
IN YOU, MY DEAR.
SHE'S WORKING WITH HIM.
YOU SEE, MR. MERRIWEATHER,
NOT ONLY DO I INTEND
TO CREATE A NEW FUTURE,
I INTEND TO CREATE
A NEW WORLD.
AT EACH ONE OF THESE POINTS,
I HAVE HIDDEN
A NEW FORM OF LASER--
ONE THAT CAN PENETRATE
THE EARTH'S CRUST
DOWN INTO THE MANTLE ITSELF.
THE GLOBAL EARTHQUAKES.
THOSE WERE ONLY TESTS.
SOON I WILL ACTIVATE
ALL OF THESE LASERS TOGETHER
AND WHEN I DO,
THEY WILL PRODUCE
WORLDWIDE EARTHQUAKES
THE LIKES OF WHICH
WE HAVE NEVER
FELT BEFORE.
KILLING EVERYONE
ON THE PLANET.
MORE THAN THAT.
THERE COMES A TIME
WHEN A HOUSE HAS BEEN
SO DAMAGED BY TERMITES
THAT YOU MUST NOT ONLY
KILL THE TERMITES,
BUT DEMOLISH THE HOUSE
AND BUILD AGAIN.
THE QUAKES ARE ONLY
A MINOR SIDE EFFECT.
THE REAL GOAL OF THIS PROJECT
IS TO HAVE THESE LASERS OF MINE
PRODUCE MASSIVE FISSURES
IN THE EARTH'S CRUST,
RELEASING MILLIONS OF TONS
OF MOLTEN LAVA.
NOW, MR. MERRIWEATHER,
YOU'RE THE GEOLOGIST.
TELL ME, WHAT HAPPENS NEXT?
ONCE THAT MUCH LAVA
IS RELEASED,
THE TECTONIC PLATES
WOULD BEGIN TO SETTLE.
AND THE SURFACE OF THE PLANET
WILL SHRINK
JUST LIKE LETTING AIR
OUT OF A BALLOON.
BUT IF THE SURFACE
OF THE EARTH SHRINKS,
THE OCEANS...
WILL COVER THE EARTH.
DIABOLICAL.
VISIONARY.
I AM GOING TO LET
MANKIND BEGIN ANEW...
HERE... ON THIS ISLAND PARADISE.
THE ONLY PLACE
THAT WILL REMAIN ABOVE WATER
ON MY BRAVE NEW WORLD.
AND THAT IS WHY I HAVE GATHERED
THE FINEST MINDS, THE VERY BEST
THAT MANKIND HAS TO OFFER.
WE WILL REPOPULATE
AND START A NEW HUMAN RACE.
PITY
YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO JOIN US.
ARE YOU REVOKING
MY INVITATION?
OH, I INTEND TO DO MORE
THAN THAT, MR. BASHIR.
NOT ONLY HAVE I BROUGHT
THE GREATEST MINDS
TO MY MOUNTAIN RETREAT,
BUT I HAVE ALSO HIRED
THE GREATEST PROTECTION
THAT MONEY CAN BUY.
I BELIEVE
YOU ALREADY KNOW...
MY NEWEST EMPLOYEE.
IS ALL THIS
REALLY NECESSARY?
IT'S THE BEST I CAN DO.
HOW LONG UNTIL
WE'RE READY
TO TRY RETRIEVING
THEIR PATTERNS?
I'D SAY ANOTHER HOUR.
( sighs )
O'BRIEN'S GOING TO KILL ME
WHEN HE GETS BACK.
THIS IS ONE OF 74 LASERS
THAT I'VE DEPLOYED
AROUND THE WORLD.
WHEN I THROW THAT SWITCH,
IT WILL BEGIN
A FIVE-MINUTE COUNTDOWN
THAT EVEN I CAN'T STOP.
AND ONCE THE LASER FIRES,
THE WHOLE CAVE
WILL BE FILLED
WITH MOLTEN LAVA.
WHERE'S COLONEL KOMANANOV?
SHE'S A SPIRITED
INDIVIDUAL.
YOUNG...
HEALTHY.
WE'LL NEED WOMEN LIKE HER
TO HELP PROPAGATE
THE SECOND HUMAN RACE.
TRY TO STAY COOL, MR. BASHIR.
Garak:
SO WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
Bashir: I'M THINKING.
THINK FAST.
I DON'T KNOW IF I'VE MADE THIS
EXPLICIT TO YOU OR NOT, DOCTOR,
BUT I REALLY DON'T WANT TO DIE
CHAINED TO A 20th-CENTURY LASER.
I THINK IT'S TIME TO END
THIS PROGRAM.
WE CAN'T DO THAT.
WE'D WIPE OUT THE PATTERNS
OF SISKO AND THE OTHERS.
THEN MAY I SUGGEST CALLING
COMMANDER EDDINGTON
AND HAVING HIM
SEND SOMEONE IN HERE
TO REMOVE THESE HANDCUFFS?
YOU HEARD WHAT ODO SAID--
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT'LL HAPPEN
IF WE INTERRUPT
THE HOLO-IMAGING ARRAY
BY CALLING FOR THE DOORS.
THE ENTIRE PROGRAM MIGHT
COLLAPSE AND KILL THEM ALL.
WELL, I ONLY KNOW
ONE THING FOR SURE, DOCTOR,
THAT WHEN THE MOLTEN LAVA
BEGINS POURING INTO THIS CAVE,
YOU AND I ARE GOING TO BE
VERY UNCOMFORTABLE.
( footsteps approaching)
WHO'S THAT?
IT'S OUR TICKET OUT OF HERE.
WHAT A WASTE...
THAT NO ONE CAN SEE
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN YOU ARE.
IS THAT YOUR PLAN?
SHUT UP.
NOAH ONLY WANTS YOU
FOR YOUR MIND.
HE CAN'T APPRECIATE
THE WOMAN INSIDE YOU.
HONEY,
WOULD YOU GRANT ME
ONE LAST REQUEST
AND TAKE OFF THOSE GLASSES?
LIKE THIS?
YES.
YOU KNOW,
YOUR HAIR WOULD LOOK
SO MUCH BETTER
IF IT WERE FREE.
I MUST SAY, DOCTOR,
THIS IS MORE THAN I EVER
WANTED TO KNOW
ABOUT YOUR FANTASY LIFE.
THERE...
THAT'S THE LAST THING
I WANT TO REMEMBER
BEFORE I DIE.
THANK YOU.
I'D GIVE YOU BOTH
SOME PRIVACY IF I COULD.
GREAT PLAN.
NOW CAN WE CALL EDDINGTON?
THAT WILL NOT BE NECESSARY.
HONEY HAS GIVEN ME
ALL WE NEED.
KISS THE GIRL,
GET THE KEY.
THEY NEVER TAUGHT ME THAT
IN THE OBSIDIAN ORDER.
COME ON!
WE HAVE TO GET
TO THE CONTROL ROOM.
WHAT?!
IF THIS PROGRAM ENDS
LIKE THE OTHERS,
EITHER KOMANANOV OR HONEY BARE
WILL BE KILLED BY DR. NOAH.
THE OTHER'S SUPPOSED TO
END UP WITH ME.
IN EITHER CASE,
WE HAVE TO MAKE SURE
THAT BOTH OF THEM SURVIVE.
YOU EXPECT TO TAKE ON NOAH
AND HIS MEN WITH THAT?
IT'S MY FANTASY.
TRUST ME.
NO!
THIS HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
IT'S TIME TO CUT OUR LOSSES.
WE CAN'T DO THAT.
KIRA OR DAX MIGHT...
YES, THEY MIGHT BE KILLED,
AND THAT IS UNFORTUNATE
BUT THERE COMES A TIME
WHEN THE ODDS ARE AGAINST YOU,
AND THE ONLY REASONABLE
COURSE OF ACTION IS TO QUIT.
QUIT?
YES!
IS THAT WHAT THEY TAUGHT YOU
IN THE OBSIDIAN ORDER?
TO GIVE UP
WHEN THINGS GET TOUGH?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THEY DID.
THAT'S WHY I'VE MANAGED
TO STAY ALIVE
WHILE MOST OF MY
COLLEAGUES ARE DEAD--
BECAUSE I KNOW
WHEN TO WALK AWAY,
AND THAT TIME
IS NOW. NOW!
AND YOU'D KNOW THAT,
DOCTOR, IF YOU WERE
A REAL
INTELLIGENCE AGENT.
OH, SO THAT'S
WHAT THIS IS ALL ABOUT.
THE FACT THAT MY FANTASY
HAPPENS TO STEP ON
WHAT YOU CONSIDER TO BE
YOUR PRIVATE DOMAIN.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, GARAK?
HAVE I BRUISED YOUR EGO
BY PLAY-ACTING AT SOMETHING
YOU TAKE SO VERY SERIOUSLY?
THAT'S SOMETHING ELSE
YOU'VE YET TO LEARN, DOCTOR.
A REAL INTELLIGENCE AGENT
HAS NO EGO, NO CONSCIENCE,
NO REMORSE-- ONLY A SENSE
OF PROFESSIONALISM,
AND MINE IS TELLING ME
THAT IT'S TIME TO GO.
COMPUTER!
DON'T!
OR WHAT?
YOU'LL KILL ME?
IF YOU CALL FOR THE EXIT,
YOU MIGHT KILL SISKO
AND THE OTHERS,
AND I AM NOT PREPARED
TO RISK THAT.
I'M AFRAID I DON'T BELIEVE
YOU'LL PULL THAT TRIGGER.
I WOULDN'T BE SO SURE
ABOUT THAT.
IT'S TIME
TO FACE REALITY, DOCTOR.
YOU'RE A MAN
WHO DREAMS OF BEING A HERO
BECAUSE YOU KNOW, DEEP DOWN,
THAT YOU'RE NOT.
I'M NO HERO EITHER,
BUT I DO KNOW
HOW TO MAKE A CHOICE,
AND I AM CHOOSING
TO SAVE MYSELF.
COMPUTER, SHOW ME
THE MECHANISM...
YOU'LL BE FINE.
IT'S JUST A FLESH WOUND.
THAT WAS AWFULLY CLOSE.
WHAT IF YOU'D KILLED ME?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I WASN'T TRYING?
DOCTOR, I DO BELIEVE
THERE'S HOPE FOR YOU YET.
I'M SO RELIEVED.
NOW WE HAVE TO GET
TO THE CONTROL ROOM.
ARE YOU COMING OR NOT?
WELL, WHO AM I TO QUESTION
JULIAN BASHIR, SECRET AGENT?
LEAD ON.
EVERYBODY STAY
WHERE YOU ARE.
JULIAN.
YOUR WEAPON, DR. NOAH.
THIS IS YOUR DOING.
YOU LET THEM GO.
I'M SORRY, DOCTOR.
JULIAN, YOU ARE JUST IN TIME.
HE WAS ABOUT TO ACTIVATE
THE FINAL SEQUENCE
OF THE LASERS.
KILL HIM, JULIAN.
NOT THIS TIME, ANA.
THEN I WILL.
NO!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
MAKING A MISTAKE.
THANK YOU,
MR. DUCHAMPS.
Eddington to Bashir.
We're going to try
rematerializing
their patterns
in about two minutes.
UNDERSTOOD.
AND WHAT IS IT YOU UNDERSTAND,
MR. BASHIR?
THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE KILLED ME
WHEN YOU HAD THE CHANCE?
I AGREE.
BUT, THEN AGAIN, I SUPPOSE
IT WOULDN'T BE VERY... HEROIC.
I, ON THE OTHER HAND,
HAVE NO PRETENSIONS
ABOUT THE IDEA OF BEING A HERO.
WAIT!
MAYBE I'M TIRED
OF BEING A HERO.
MAYBE I'VE THOUGHT OVER
WHAT YOU'VE SAID,
AND DECIDED
THAT YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
ABOUT WHAT?
EVERYTHING--
THE DECADENCE
OF THE WORLD,
THE NEED FOR ORDER.
THE MORE I THINK ABOUT IT,
THE MORE I REALIZE
THAT YOUR WAY
MAY BE THE ONLY WAY.
HA!
YOU EXPECT ME
TO BELIEVE THAT?
YOU ARE JULIAN BASHIR,
A MAN WHO HAS SPENT
HIS ENTIRE LIFE
DEDICATED TO FIGHTING AGAINST...
YES!
BUT THAT'S ALL ABOUT
TO END NOW, ISN'T IT?
YOU'RE GOING TO DESTROY THIS
WORLD AND START A NEW ONE.
WHAT'S THE USE OF ME CONTINUING
TO DEFEND A DOOMED PLANET?
CAN YOU SEE
THE SENSE IN THAT?
NO.
I'M AN INTELLIGENCE AGENT,
AND IF THERE'S
ANY ONE THING I'VE LEARNED,
IT IS THAT THERE COMES A POINT
WHEN THE ODDS ARE AGAINST YOU
AND THERE IS NO REASONABLE
COURSE OF ACTION BUT TO QUIT.
HOW DO YOU THINK I'VE MANAGED
TO STAY ALIVE SO LONG
WHEN ALL OF MY COMPATRIOTS
ARE DEAD?
IT IS BECAUSE I HAVE KNOWN
WHEN TO WALK AWAY.
ROM TO OPS, I'M READY.
YOU CAN START TRANSFERRING
THE NEURAL ENERGY
TO THE DEFIANT.
Acknowledged.
BEGINNING DATA TRANSFER.
YOU MAKE A VERY INTERESTING
ARGUMENT, MR. BASHIR.
BUT I'M AFRAID I'VE BEEN
LOOKING FORWARD TO KILLING YOU
FOR A LONG TIME.
YOU NEED TO MOVE BEYOND THAT.
YOU NEED TO START THINKING
ABOUT YOUR NEW WORLD ORDER.
YOU MAY EVEN NEED
SOMEONE LIKE ME.
IF YOU THINK
THAT BY GOING OVER THERE,
YOU ARE GOING TO DESTROY
MY CONTROL CONSOLE,
YOU ARE WASTING YOUR TIME.
I DON'T INTEND
TO DESTROY YOUR CONSOLE, DOCTOR.
I INTEND TO USE IT.
YOU'VE JUST ACTIVATED
THE FINAL LASER SEQUENCE.
YOU'VE DESTROYED THE WORLD.
Odo:
DATA TRANSFER COMPLETE.
I AM REESTABLISHING
COMPUTER CONTROL
OVER THE STATION.
O'Brien:
IT'S WORKING
JUST AS YOU PLANNED.
YOU'VE DONE IT DOCTOR.
YES.
BUT SOMEHOW,
I DIDN'T EXPECT TO WIN.
I SUPPOSE
THE ONLY THING LEFT TO DO NOW
IS TO KILL YOU.
WHAT HAPPENED, COMMANDER?
WHAT DID YOU DO
TO MY SHIP?
Eddington:
IT'S GOING TO TAKE
SOME EXPLAINING.
EDDINGTON TO BASHIR.
WE'VE GOT THEM, DOCTOR.
You can leave the holosuite now.
THANK YOU.
INTERESTING.
YOU SAVED THE DAY
BY DESTROYING THE WORLD.
I BET THEY DIDN'T
TEACH YOU THAT
AT THE OBSIDIAN ORDER.
NO, THERE WAS A GREAT DEAL
THEY DIDN'T TEACH ME.
LIKE THE VALUE
OF A GOOD GAME OF CHANCE,
OR HOW INDULGING
IN FANTASY
KEEPS THE MIND CREATIVE.
LUNCH TOMORROW?
OF COURSE.
BUT WHY DON'T WE
HAVE IT AT YOUR PLACE...
IN HONG KONG.
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
THIS WAS YOUR LAST MISSION.
OH, I THINK
IT'S SAFE TO SAY
THAT JULIAN BASHIR,
SECRET AGENT, WILL RETURN.
HMM...