One raktajino, extra hot,
two measures of kava.
Time?
0759 hours.
Ah.
Good morning.
Major.
So...
How many have we got?
16 items.
Oh, the station's criminal
element has been busy this week.
Oh, nothing
out of the ordinary.
Three petty thefts
two incidents
of disorderly conduct
one assault...
Ijarna's wife hit him again?
Why does he stay with her?
Skip to item 12.
"Public lewdness."
The same night
Ijarna reported the assault
I found him and his wife...
behind the Information Kiosk
on the second level.
That answers my question.
What about item seven?
Ah.
One of my deputies
caught Oguy Jel
scrawling political graffiti
on a wall in Section 4.
He's always riled up
about something, isn't he?
What is it this time?
He was protesting
First Minister Shakaar's
upcoming visit to the station.
He's been handing out
leaflets saying
Shakaar should drop the petition
to join the Federation.
Well, leaflets are one thing.
Vandalism is quite another.
Oguy spent a night in a holding
cell for his trouble
and I understand the Arbiter
has sentenced him to three weeks
community service...
on sanitation duty.
Just make sure
he scrubs that wall clean
before Shakaar gets here.
I don't want him to see it.
Right.
I'd like to file a complaint.
Not now, Quark.
A noise complaint against you.
We are conducting
station business.
My quarters are right below his.
You wouldn't believe
the racket he makes.
Quark!
Do you know what it's like
to hear someone
practice shape-shifting?
Last night, it sounded
like a Takaran wildebeest
was tromping around up there.
That was
for all of five minutes.
Once you complained, I took
the form of a Rafalian mouse.
Yeah, little tiny feet
skittering across the floor.
Back and forth,
back and forth.
You could hear that?
Hello?
Sometimes I can even
hear him... oozing around.
Well, maybe you should
change quarters.
Maybe he should have
a little more consideration.
Shape-shifting
in the middle of the night...
there ought to be a
regulation against that.
Come back in half an hour.
I'll be happy to take
your complaint then.
Oh, I'll be back.
You can count on it.
It's just Quark's luck
that you would be assigned
quarters right above his.
Luck had nothing to do with it.
I don't know why Captain Sisko
insists on having me here.
I'm not a senior officer.
Well, maybe he just
wanted to see you
in your dress uniform.
It does show off your figure.
Why, thank you.
Good of you to make it, old man.
Shakaar's transport just docked.
Sorry. There were so many
people on the Promenade.
It was hard to get through.
I hope Shakaar's gotten better
at speaking in front of groups.
He used to mumble his way
through mission briefings.
Everyone in our resistance cell
had to learn to lip-read.
Welcome to Deep Space 9,
Minister.
Well, thank you, Captain.
I've been looking forward
to visiting the station
and to meeting the Emissary.
Uh... this is part
of my senior staff.
Lieutenant Commander Jadzia Dax.
Chief of Operations
Miles O'Brien.
Doctor Bashir, and, of course
you know Major Kira.
Nerys.
Good to see you again, Edon.
Well, I guess I should introduce
my senior staff.
There he is.
Sarish Rez,
the First Minister's adjutant.
A pleasure.
Come this way.
There's quite a crowd
on the Promenade
waiting to see you.
Oh, can't wait.
Why didn't you tell me?
What?
He's so good looking.
The guards will escort you
to the podium
whenever you're ready.
Don't forget to mention
the transit subsidies
you just allocated.
Tell them they
can expect the price
of transport to Bajor
to start dropping
within a few months,
and remember... enunciate.
Let's go.
Good luck.
Yeah.
Odo to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead, Constable.
I've just received
a disturbing communication.
I have reason to believe
someone is planning
to assassinate
First Minister Shakaar.
As far as I'm concerned,
we should have gotten
the First Minister
off that podium
as soon as we received
the information.
If Shakaar canceled
his public appearances
every time someone
threatened his life
he would never leave his office.
We're not talking about
some disgruntled shopkeeper
who writes a letter
threatening Shakaar
for raising his taxes.
We're talking about
a Cardassian extremist group
that's already succeeded
in assassinating
two Bajoran officials.
I know all about "The True Way"
and what they're capable of.
My sources in the Cardassian
civilian government
believe The True Way already
has an operative in place
aboard the station.
I suggest you cancel
the First Minister's conference
and reschedule it
at another location.
Absolutely not.
Nothing is going to keep Shakaar
from meeting
those delegates tomorrow.
Bajor's effort
to join the Federation
hinges on what happens
over the next few days.
Shouldn't the decision be up
to the First Minister?
It will be.
But I already know
what he's going to say.
So do I.
Shakaar knows better than anyone
you can't capitulate
to terrorists.
He used to be one
and the day the Cardassians
started to negotiate with him
was the day he knew
they'd been beaten.
He'll stay.
I suppose if I were
in his position,
I'd do the same.
Constable, I want station
security stepped up
for the duration
of Shakaar's visit.
The First Minister will have
round-the-clock protection.
I'd like to deploy
Starfleet Security personnel
in addition to my own deputies.
Of course.
Commander Eddington is on leave.
I'll ask Mr. Worf
to head up Starfleet Security
while he's gone.
I have cleared the rooms above,
below and to both sides
of the First Minister's
quarters.
I would recommend clearing
that entire section
of the Habitat Ring.
I'm afraid that isn't feasible.
There are over 1,200
people living there.
Providing security
was difficult enough
aboard the Enterprise.
It appears to be next
to impossible on this station.
It isn't easy.
I prefer a more...
orderly environment.
We have that in common.
My people have
an innate need for order.
How do you tolerate living here?
I make order where I can.
For one thing,
I have a daily routine
which I follow unwaveringly.
The shopkeepers on the Promenade
joke that they can set
their clocks by me.
Unfortunately,
I have found it difficult
to establish a routine here.
There are other ways to create
order in your life...
your quarters, for example.
Everything in mine
has its specific place
and it's all arranged just so.
Yes, mine, too.
Even with my eyes closed
I would still know
where everything was.
Exactly.
I would not tolerate it
any other way.
I'll tell you what else to do.
Make sure everyone knows
they can't just drop by
your quarters to say "hello."
If someone does, whatever
happens, don't make them
feel welcome.
Of course not.
That would only invite
subsequent visits.
Precisely.
So far, the only person
that has a tendency to "drop by"
is Chief O'Brien.
That's probably because he
knows you from the Enterprise.
Perhaps if I am more...
inhospitable, he will stop.
Good luck.
Odo to Worf.
Go ahead.
The guards are in position.
The corridors
between Shakaar's quarters
and the Wardroom
have been cleared.
Acknowledged.
The First Minister is scheduled
to leave for the reception
in half an hour.
The Wardroom will be scanned
and secured well before then.
You must be Odo.
First Minister.
I was hoping
I'd get to meet you.
I just wish it wasn't
under these circumstances.
We're ready to go.
Well, the reception doesn't
start for another...
I know.
I want to stop by the Promenade
and visit the Temple first.
Why wasn't I told about this?
I didn't know myself
until a moment ago.
Is there a problem?
I would have posted extra
security on the Promenade.
Oh, well, we'll
just, uh, slip in.
I'll stay for a few minutes,
and then we'll slip out.
With all due respect, sir,
now that you're First Minister
you can't slip in or out of bed
without people noticing.
Maybe not, but that doesn't mean
I'm going to stay
in bed all day.
Odo to Worf.
There's been a change of plans.
I understand you used to work
for the Cardassians
when they were running
this station.
I was in charge
of keeping order
on the Promenade.
They could have given that job
to one of their own people.
They must have thought
very highly of you.
Humph.
I know Kira does.
She once told me she trusted
you with her life.
Well, I'm gratified
to hear that.
I always found her to be
a good judge of character.
So I'll trust you
with mine, too.
Oh, it's him.
First Minister.
Gentlemen, how are you?
Hi.
How are you today?
Worf to Odo.
We have secured the Temple.
I'll try to get him
inside as soon as I can.
Welcome.
Pleasure to see you here.
How do you do?
Pleasure.
It's nice to meet you.
I appreciate you being here.
Thank you.
Nice to see you.
Is it always like this?
It's not often
that people get a chance
to talk to the First Minister.
And besides, have you ever
met a Bajoran who didn't have
a fervent opinion
about everything
from prophetic interpretation
to farm policy?
I guess not.
Is that Vedek Tonsa?
Yes, it is.
I hear he's an excellent
springball player.
Oh, the best on the station.
Why?
Well, I think I'll see
if we can arrange a game.
Oh, you better be good.
I'm terrible.
But it will give me
a chance to talk to him
about supporting Shakaar
in the Vedek Assembly.
Do you have to stare like that?
I think it's making
people nervous.
Good.
You know...
I've been meaning to ask you.
Why don't you wear
that belt anymore?
I don't know.
It didn't really
serve a purpose.
It's not as if I needed it
to hold my pants up.
I just thought it
looked good on you.
That's all.
Really?
Really.
Well...
if you say so.
Better?
Much.
I guess I'll turn in.
Of course.
Good night, Major.
Good night.
Will you excuse me?
Nerys...
where are you going?
You haven't even said hello.
You were so busy.
I didn't want to bother you.
You wouldn't be bothering me.
You'd be rescuing me.
That bad?
You have no idea.
Then I supposed now wouldn't
be a good time for me
to give you my opinion
on how Bajor
should be dealing
with the Klingons.
Actually, it would.
But not here.
I was joking.
Fine.
We'll talk
about something else.
Care for some hasperat?
You know I don't eat.
Have some.
I'm charging by the head
for this little function
and you do have a head...
for the moment.
Let's take a walk.
Okay.
Minister?
Uh, we're going
to take a stroll.
If you tell me
where you're going
I'll secure your route.
If I knew
where we were going
it wouldn't be a stroll,
would it?
I suppose not.
I'll escort you.
Fine, but, uh, just you.
Oh, and, uh, don't
stay too close, huh?
Let's go.
Where?
Back to my quarters.
This way.
I take it the negotiations
aren't going all that well.
How'd you know?
The truth is the Bajorans
are even less successful
than most humanoids
at hiding their emotions.
So you're saying it's as plain
as the nose on my face?
I've been working
with the Federation
for a number of years.
They claim to be
open and understanding
but, somehow, they're always
convinced that they're right.
It can be exasperating
at times.
I've been trying to get them
to cut the timetable
for Bajor's admittance
into the Federation by half
but every time
I think I've made them
understand my reasons,
they remind me
that every member
of the Federation
has gone through
the same admittance process.
And why should Bajor
be any different?
I can't think
of a single reason.
Unless, of course, you take
into account the effect
that 50 years of occupation
might have on a society.
Thank you.
You know, I've been a soldier
and I've been a politician
and I have to say
I'm beginning to think
that being a soldier was easier.
Ahh...
Well, I'm afraid I don't
know much about politics.
Well, you agree with me.
As far as I'm concerned,
that makes you an expert.
I realize I haven't been
making your job any easier
the past few days.
Well, I can't argue with that.
Well, I just want you
to understand
that, uh, I appreciate
your thoroughness.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Odo, uh...
I know that you
and Nerys are friends
and I was wondering...
does she ever talk
to you about me?
Of course.
She's spoken about you
on more than one occasion.
Well, what I mean is, has
she ever said anything to you
that might indicate
that she...
thought of me
as more than a friend?
Ah.
Well, let me think.
No.
Oh, I see.
Oh, I've... I've known Nerys
for over ten years.
Uh...
I've trusted her with my life
on more than one occasion.
So have I.
She always knew
how to follow orders.
She never complained
when things got rough.
She was a good soldier.
A good friend.
But now it's...
it's different.
Is it?
She's still your friend.
I know.
I think I'm falling in love
with her.
Sometimes, I get
the sense that maybe
just maybe...
she feels the same way...
but I could be wrong.
I'm afraid to say anything
because it, it might
ruin our friendship.
But if I don't, I could be
letting something very precious
slip through my fingers.
It's a...
difficult situation.
Yeah.
Well, for all I know
I've gotten myself
all twisted up over nothing.
I mean, if she hasn't
said anything to you
then this whole thing is
probably just inside my head.
Frankly, I think
she's still grieving
for Vedek Bareil.
Oh, of course.
It's only natural.
Maybe I should just be patient.
That's what I would do.
On the other hand
maybe I should let
her know how I feel.
It might help her
to get over her loss
if she knew that
there was somebody
who really cared about her.
What do you think?
I'm afraid I know even less
about relationships
than I do about politics.
Well, I understand.
I... I don't mean
to burden you
with my problems.
Talking about
humanoid relationships
can't be
that interesting to you.
For the most part, no.
You don't have to bother.
I can personally vouch
for every one of my employees
who had access to that food.
Ha.
I can't tell you
how relieved that makes me feel.
I'm reading some sort
of power signature.
Ah...
A Ferengi eavesdropping device.
I don't suppose you know
anything about this.
Oh! There it is.
I've been looking
for that all day.
You admit it's yours?
I must have misplaced it.
I take it you were hoping
to peddle information
about Shakaar's meeting.
Odo, you know
as well as I do
that it's illegal to listen
to someone's conversation
without their consent.
Why else would
someone like you
own such an expensive
listening devise?
I use it to monitor
Rom's sleep.
You see, ever since he was a boy
my brother's had this condition
where he sometimes
stops breathing
in the middle of the night.
The fact is... I can't sleep
unless I know he's all right.
Very touching.
Oh!
How clumsy of me.
You are in a bad mood today.
I don't have moods.
Of course not.
You're an unfeeling changeling.
All you care about is order.
That's right.
Oh, please.
I know what's going on.
You don't have to pretend
with me.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
You're in love with her.
Who?
Kira.
That's ridiculous!
And what's more, you're worried
she's falling in love
with Shakaar.
Is that a fact?
It's the truth.
Why can't you just admit it?
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Look, Odo, I know
this can't be easy for...
I don't want
your sympathy, Quark
and I don't need your advice!
Just stay out of my business!
Computer, time.
0821 hours.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I didn't realize
what time it was.
So what do we have?
Nine items.
Well, so far it's all
fairly routine.
Something wrong?
Your raktajino?
Oh! I had one this morning
with Shakaar.
I... I didn't see you
in the Replimat.
No, it was in his quarters.
He asked me to look over
a proposal he's going to make
to the Federation delegates.
Ahh...
There's an interesting story
behind item four.
And I would love
to hear it, but I'm
a little pressed for time
right now.
Of course.
I promised Shakaar I'd give him
a tour of the station.
I'll make sure
security is in place.
Thank you.
See you later.
The Upper Pylons have the
best view of the wormhole.
I've never seen it, actually.
Why don't we wait
a few minutes?
Maybe a ship will go through.
You can see it open.
Well, you're the First Officer.
Can't you...
order a ship through?
Well, you're the First Minister.
You should be able to order
a whole fleet through.
The other day,
I heard someone say
that if you happen
to see the wormhole open
you get to make a wish.
Oh. That's been going around
the station for a while now.
Uh-huh.
Look.
Did you make a wish?
Yes.
We should get going.
There's a lot more to see.
Odo to Worf.
Go ahead.
We're heading back down
to the Docking Ring.
Acknowledged.
Your route has been secured.
Level 2-D.
Please enter security code.
You know, I, um...
haven't had a meal
outside the Wardroom,
or my quarters,
since I got here.
Well, there's some
pretty nice places to eat
on the Promenade.
You have a favorite?
There's a new
Bolian restaurant
that's pretty good.
I've never had Bolian food.
Well, this isn't going
to sound very appetizing
but the meat they use is...
sort of... aged.
Aged.
Worf to Odo.
A turbolift is stuck
on Level 41.
We are going to have
to reroute you.
Verify your security code
and I'll release the controls
to you.
You don't want to know.
Why don't we go
there tonight?
I'd love to.
Great.
How does 1900 hours sound?
We can...
We're falling!
Kira to Worf.
Someone cut our com links.
Controls aren't responding.
Well...
I guess this means
my tour is over.
You're telling me
someone overrode
the station's com system,
faked Worf's voice
and then sent one
of our turbolifts
into a free fall?
I'm afraid so, sir.
Apparently, they tapped
into the com system
with a voice synthesizer.
What I want to know is
how they got Worf's
security code.
We don't know
that they did that, sir.
What do you mean?
I turned over control
of the turbolift
without verifying his code.
They say to err is human.
But you're not human, Odo.
You're not even humanoid.
And this is not
the sort of mistake
that I'd expect from you.
I...
was distracted.
Distracted?
A personal matter, sir.
I'd prefer not to discuss it.
Constable...
whatever this personal matter is
don't let it interfere
with your job again.
I won't, sir.
That's all I need to hear.
Now, no ships have been
allowed to leave
since this incident occurred.
That means whoever
was responsible
is still on the station.
I want them found.
Yes, sir.
It appears that they accessed
the turbolift control system
through the ODN relays.
There might be a trace
of the access signal
left in the relays.
If we can isolate it
we might be able to follow
it back to the source.
Odo!
Are you listening?
I've heard every word.
Your mind does not appear
to be on its work.
With all due respect, Commander,
you don't know me well enough
to gauge my state of mind.
When someone fails
to ask for a security
verification
their state of mind is obvious.
Is it?
With all due respect
I do not see how sitting
in a chair, staring at a wall
is going to help apprehend
Shakaar's would-be assassin.
You're right.
It won't.
I'm going to talk to Major Kira.
Why? She already gave
us her statement.
You follow your leads,
Commander.
I'll follow mine.
Jimenez.
What are these men doing here?
First Minister Shakaar's
in Major Kira's quarters, sir.
How long has he been there?
Since they finished dinner.
About three hours ago.
All right, Ensign,
you're relieved.
Sir, I'm not scheduled
to go off duty...
I said you're relieved.
I'll take the rest
of your shift.
Yes, sir.
Let's have dinner.
Great.
I'll see you then.
Good morning.
May I ask where you're
going, First Minister?
To my quarters
and then to the meeting
in the Wardroom.
Major
I was wondering
if you had a moment
to answer a few questions
about what happened
in the turbolift?
Sure, come on in.
Lights.
Did I do something amusing?
No. It's...
Edon and I...
Oh, I understand.
Oh, Odo...
if someone had told me
a year ago
that this was going to happen
do you know
what I would have said?
"You're crazy.
"Yes, I respect him,
yes, I...
"He makes me laugh, bu-but we
know each other too well.
"I mean, he's seen me
go weeks without a bath.
"We've spent long cold nights
huddled together for warmth.
"There's no mystery left
between us.
We're friends, that's all."
I guess I was wrong.
I'm happy for you.
This must seem so silly to you.
No.
Not in the least.
You are such
a good friend to me.
I'm so glad you're
the first person to know.
Oh, now, um...
you wanted to ask me something
about what happened
in the turbolift.
Yes, but we can talk
about it later.
Oh no, are you sure?
Yes.
I have an appointment.
All right.
Take him to a holding cell.
What'd he do?
He was responsible
for the attack
on First Minister Shakaar.
What?
He has admitted to being
a True Way operative.
They provided him with
an isolinear interface
to access station systems.
He was attempting to use it
to depressurize
Shakaar's quarters
by sabotaging
the environmental controls.
I see.
When he tried to access them
I traced the signal path
back to him.
He was operating
out of an abandoned
cargo hold on Level 31.
Why didn't you call me
before you made the arrest?
It was not necessary.
Your deputies assisted me
quite capably.
They are well-trained.
You are to be commended.
I know you're in there.
I heard you.
Fine.
We'll do this the hard way.
I knew it would come to this.
You take the form
of an animal
you're going to end up
behaving like one.
What was it?
A Klingon targ?
A Trellan crocodile?
I tell you, this time,
you've crossed the line.
I've had it!
Odo?
Odo!
Are you okay?
You were right.
Oh.
I take it Major Kira
and Shakaar are...
You really are in love.
I must say
I really didn't think
you had it in you.
It takes passion
to do something like this
and I always thought
you were colder
than a Breen winter.
What was I thinking?
How could I have fooled myself
into believing she could ever
love someone like me?
Look, uh...
the last thing I want to do
is interfere
with your personal life
but this, uh...
this just isn't any good...
for either of us.
I'll try to keep my problems
more quiet next time.
I'm not talking
about the noise.
I'm talking about business.
I'm losing my shirt
in the manhunt pool.
The what?
Anytime there's an unusual crime
committed on this station,
I run a pool
so that people can bet
on how long it'll take
for you to catch
the perpetrator.
It's very popular.
Frankly, I don't care
whether you and Major Kira
end up living happily
ever after or not.
I just want to see
the situation resolved.
And the way I see it
you've either got to
tell her how you feel
or forget about her and
get on with your life.
Concentrate on the essentials...
because you can't
keep going like this.
It's interfering with your job
and my profits.
Your profits.
Unless you do something
about this situation
I'm going to have
to stop running the pool.
I'm devastated.
You should be.
The fact that the pool exists
says something about you...
about who you are.
People see you as the guy
who always gets his man.
Now, you're becoming the guy
who tears up his quarters
and sits alone in the rubble.
And no one's going
to want to place bets
on how long someone's going
to sit around in the dark.
Well...
I've said my piece.
Sorry for butting in.
But I'm just looking
out for my business.
Funny.
For a minute there, I thought
you were talking to me...
as a friend.
Nah.
Yes.
Good morning, Major.
Oh, come in.
What brings you here?
I wanted to talk to you
about something.
What is it?
I...
don't quite know
how to say this...
but I've given it
a lot of thought...
and, uh...
Well, go on.
Just say it.
I am afraid
I won't be able to make
our Tuesday morning meetings
anymore.
Oh.
Why not?
I've decided to schedule
additional training exercises
with my deputies.
Maybe we could have our meetings
at another time.
My schedule is rather tight.
And let's face it
the criminal activity reports
speak for themselves.
There's really no reason
we have to review them together.
Maybe not,
but I kind of enjoyed doing it.
I thought you did, too.
Of course.
Odo...
is something wrong?
It's just a matter of using
my time more efficiently.
I understand.
Well.
Hey.
No belt?
I'm just trying to keep
to the essentials, Major.
See you.
They're upstairs.
Who?
Kira and Shakaar.
They're in Holosuite 3
practicing the speech
he's going to give tomorrow
before he leaves.
I hear he's going
to announce
that the Federation has
agreed to cut the timetable
on Bajor's admittance.
Where did you hear that?
Just a rumor.
Are you sure you haven't been
listening in on your holosuites
again?
Even if I wanted to,
I couldn't.
I don't have
the right equipment.
Hmm, not anymore.
By the way
I dropped by your quarters
this morning.
Oh?
I heard some noise,
and when I went to complain
I found a work crew
installing soundproofing
in the floor.
I have to say, Odo,
I'm touched that you
would do something
like that for me.
I'm having the floor
reinforced.
The fact that they're
soundproofing it as well
is incidental.
Mm-hmm.
If you think I'd put up
with three days of construction
for your sake, think again.
I guess I should have known.
Thanks anyway.
Don't mention it.
Hmm.
What?
That's what she said.
No! I don't believe it.
Okay, from the beginning.
Tell me the whole thing.
Well, they're either going
to do it, or they're not...