Is all this really necessary?
The Klingon invasion
has all but destroyed
the Cardassian health system.
They're suffering outbreaks
of all kinds of diseases
and in epidemic proportions.
Besides, you've only got
12 more inoculations to go.
Twelve?
Sorry, but if you want
to go to the conference...
I don't want to go.
I'm no diplomat.
Going to some obscure
Cardassian outpost
to share Bajoran intelligence
about the Klingons
isn't exactly
something I'm good at.
I don't know why I even agreed
to go in the first place.
You agreed to go because
it was a personal request
from the First Minister
of Bajor.
Oh, it was a personal request,
all right.
Shakaar took me to my favorite
restaurant in Jalanda City
poured me glass after glass
of spring wine
and then took me to his home
and gave me a massage
with Kolaish spice oil.
Well... nice to know
he's keeping in touch
with his constituents.
It wasn't fair.
I mean, I would have said yes
to anything at that point.
Ah... Ah...
What is it?
I'm seeing spots.
Big, green swirling ones?
The size of Alvinian melons.
And is the room
beginning to spin?
Yes.
Good. It means the vaccine's
beginning to work.
Everything will settle down
in a moment.
Major, may I speak with you?
Uh, I'm not going anywhere.
This one's going to make you
feel a little queasy.
Ah.
If you have something
to say to the Major
you better make it fast.
The Federation has some concerns
about your upcoming meeting
with the Cardassians.
So do I.
There are certain
technological advances
that we have shared with
both Bajor and the Klingons
that we'd prefer to keep
out of Cardassian hands.
Such as?
Photon torpedo
guidance systems...
long-range sensors...
enhanced warp core overdrives.
This is a complete list.
Oh. Well...
I think the Cardassians
are going to be
a little disappointed.
Undoubtedly.
Is that all?
Yes.
Oh, good.
I'll be right back.
I'm glad I'm not going
to Cardassia.
Come in.
Hello, Major.
Dukat...
what are you doing here?
I'm to escort you
to your meeting on Korma.
You're commanding the Groumall?
Thanks to you.
If you had not convinced me
to bring my half-Bajoran
daughter back to Cardassia
I'd still be
Chief Military Advisor
to the Detapa Council.
They demoted you.
Exactly one week
after my mother disowned me
and my wife took
our children and left.
You still did
the right thing, Dukat.
And as a reward
for following your advice
I have been relegated
to ferrying freight.
And, occasionally
various foreign dignitaries,
such as yourself.
Look, if it makes you
feel better to blame me
go right ahead.
No, no, no.
I blame no one...
but myself.
I was indiscreet.
I compromised myself and have
been punished accordingly.
If someone under my command
had behaved so outrageously
I would do
the same thing to him.
Besides, I assure you, this is
only a temporary setback.
Everything I have lost...
I will regain.
It's only a matter of time.
Now...
may I take your bags?
Please?
Come in.
Ziyal...
I didn't know
you were on board.
Hello, Major.
Oh, please, call me Nerys.
So, I take it
living on Cardassia
didn't work out very well.
I wasn't exactly welcomed
with open arms.
There were some Cardassians
who could see past the Bajoran
ridges on my nose, but not many.
I'm sorry.
I know it must have been
very difficult for you.
The only good thing
about living on Cardassia
was being with my father.
I'm glad the two of you
are getting along.
He's been wonderful.
And so brave.
He never tried to hide me away.
He never acted
like he was ashamed of me.
We'd go out to dinner together,
take long walks.
And now that he's been exiled?
Wherever he goes, I go.
He's the only family I have.
And this is
the only home I need.
Your father isn't the only one
who's brave.
What's that?
It's a battle drill.
On a freighter?
Target at 400,000 kilometers
and closing.
Shields at maximum.
Maintain scan.
Engineering and tactical ready.
Waiting on weapons, sir.
What's taking so long?
The phaser banks
are still charging.
I want those weapons
on line now.
Phasers ready.
Lock on target.
Target set.
Fire!
Time.
Three forty-seven.
That's pitiful.
A crew of Ferengi scrap peddlers
could do better than that.
Select another target.
We'll do it again.
Aye, sir.
This may be a lowly freighter,
Major
but it's still a military vessel
and will be run
in a military manner.
You know...
you could speed up
your phaser recharge time
by routing power through
an anodyne capacitor.
Thank you, Major.
That's very helpful.
And if we had an anodyne
capacitor, we would use it.
But we don't.
Major...
Please forgive me.
I do appreciate your suggestion.
Any anger I may have expressed
is due to my...
frustration over the complete
inadequacy of this... vessel.
I hope you'll allow me
to make it up to you.
What did you have in mind?
I was hoping
we might have dinner together.
After all,
it is Cardassian tradition
for the Commanding Officer
of a ship
to entertain his guests.
Far be it from me to stand
in the way of tradition.
This is Bajoran spring wine.
My last bottle.
It's one of the things
I miss most about Bajor.
I talked to Ziyal.
She's a lovely girl.
I'm very glad that you
convinced me not to kill her.
Despite everything
that's happened?
You may not believe this, Major
but when it comes to Ziyal
I regret nothing.
It's good to hear that.
By the way, Major
what it this I hear
about you and Shakaar?
I don't know what you've heard.
First, it was Vedek Bareil
and now it's the head
of the Bajoran government.
You do like powerful
men, don't you?
First of all,
Shakaar's an old friend.
Second of all,
what business is it of yours?
Let's just say it's further
incentive for me to regain my...
former position.
It's good to see you haven't
lost your sense of humor.
I must say I've always admired
Shakaar's success with women.
The intelligence file I kept
on him during the occupation
is filled with reports
of his conquests.
In fact, if you
remember correctly
you were the only female
in his resistance cell
that he didn't... charm.
At least until now.
Is that what you kept track of
during the occupation?
No wonder you lost.
More wine, Major?
Another drill?
I didn't schedule one.
Sir, we're approaching
the outpost on Korma...
or what's left of it.
What are you talking about?
From what we can tell,
it's been attacked.
The planetary defense systems
have been disabled.
Every building
has been destroyed.
How many casualties?
There are no life-signs.
Then we have to assume
that everyone at the outpost
including the Cardassian and the
Bajoran dignitaries, is dead.
Sir, I'm reading
a subspace distortion
bearing 001, mark 15.
On screen.
Klingons...
They're scanning us, sir.
Full power to forward shields.
At this distance,
your shields won't mean much.
Sir, they've stopped
scanning us.
What are they doing?
Nothing, sir.
They don't seem to be in a hurry
to do anything about us.
They don't think
we're a threat, Dukat.
Then why were they cloaked
when we arrived?
They detected
an incoming vessel.
They didn't know what it was,
so they hid.
Now they know
and they're unconcerned.
The Klingon ship
has lowered its shields.
They're moving off
at one-quarter impulse.
They'll pay for their arrogance.
Charge phaser banks.
What are you doing, Dukat?
You can't go up against
a bird-of-prey.
Must I remind you, Major,
they just murdered your people
as well as mine?
I know that
but getting all of us killed
isn't going to change that.
We're the only Cardassian ship
in the area.
I'm not going to let these
Klingons escape unchallenged.
You attack them,
and all you're going to do
is give them
a little target practice.
They're going
to blow us to pieces
with their first shot.
Phaser banks charged.
Lock phasers on target.
Phasers locked.
Dukat!
At least lock on
to the underside of their hull.
It's their weakest spot.
You heard the Major.
Target set.
Fire.
Their shields were down
and we didn't penetrate
their hull.
Divert all power
to forward shields.
Aye, sir.
They've gone to warp.
Well...
it would seem we're not...
worth destroying.
Lucky for us.
I suppose
from their point of view...
there's no honor in destroying
a worthless freighter.
I have to inform
Central Command.
These Klingons
have been operating
behind our lines with impunity.
Someone has got to stop them.
Someone else.
How close is the nearest
Cardassian warship?
Probably in the Dopa system
somewhere.
That's almost three days away.
By the time they get here,
the Klingons will be long gone.
That's true, but what
can we do about it?
We can go after the Klingons.
A moment ago, you
were advising caution.
That's because a moment ago
we were in no position
to fight back.
I have no intention
of letting them get away
with what they did.
Now, you said scanners showed
that the outpost
disruptors were disabled
not destroyed, right?
Correct.
Dukat, do you think
you'd be able to repair
one of those disruptors?
What would be the point?
I doubt we can lure the Klingons
back to the outpost.
Maybe not, but there's no reason
we can't make a few
alterations to your ship.
What kind of alterations?
Here?
In the cargo hold?
Why not?
Well, because the outpost's
planetary defense weapons
are system 5 disruptors.
They were never designed
to operate aboard
a moving spacecraft.
And these cargo bays
were never designed
to hold them.
Dukat, you are going
to have to stop thinking
like a Cardassian
military officer.
And more like you?
More like a resistance fighter.
You have got to make
use of what you have.
If you need a hammer
and you don't have one
use a pipe.
And you really think
we can make those weapons
operational on this ship?
It's worth a try.
I suppose if we disable
the tractor beam
we could reroute enough power
to operate
one of the disruptors.
But those weapons are huge.
What do we do
with all this cargo?
Get rid of it.
All of it?
I realize it's traditional
for a Cardassian Captain
to take a percentage
of the haul
but you are going to have
to shed a lot of traditions
if you are serious about
fighting the Klingons.
Some traditions
are hard to break.
You'll get used to it.
You... never cease
to impress me, Major.
I have a lot
to learn from you.
Target at 500,000 kilometers.
System 5 disruptor
on line.
Open cargo bay doors.
Doors opening.
Telemetry lock confirmed.
Are you ready?
Diverting all power
to your station.
200,000 kilometers and closing.
Fire!
Very impressive, Major!
Don't be too
impressed yet, Dukat.
We still have some problems.
Firing the disruptor
ruptured power relays
and plasma circuits
all over the ship.
We have small plasma leaks
in Levels 2, 4 and 5.
I want those leaks
fixed immediately.
Aye, sir.
We're going to have
to do something
about that recoil.
Major, I'm confident
you'll have that disruptor
running so smoothly
it wouldn't wake
a sleeping child.
Why is it, when you smile,
I want to leave the room?
I suppose it's because
of my overwhelming charm.
But you must admit
it is rather amusing.
When we do destroy
that bird-of-prey
it will no doubt go a long way
toward restoring my reputation...
and I have you
to thank for it.
I'm trying not to think
about that.
Major...
why are you so reluctant
to face the obvious?
We make an excellent team.
We are not a team, Dukat
and we have nothing in common.
The only reason I'm helping you
is because those Klingons
killed 15 Bajoran diplomats.
There were Cardassians
at that outpost, too.
Maybe.
But all you care about
is redeeming yourself
in the eyes of the
Cardassian government.
You have seen an opportunity
for advancement
and you are grabbing it.
You judge me too harshly.
Maybe I am seeking to regain
my former position...
one which I earned
through hard work
dedication, and sacrifice.
But redemption is not
my sole motivation.
I care about my people
and I don't intend
to allow the Klingons
to get away
with murdering them.
I'm a much more complicated man
than you give me credit for.
Well, if that's true
I suppose I prefer simpler men.
Like Shakaar?
It amazes me that a woman
as intelligent
and sophisticated as you
could be attracted
to such a lumbering,
simplistic field hand.
I mean, what could
the two of you
possibly talk about?
That lumbering field hand
is the First Minister of Bajor
and he knows more
about how to talk to me
than you ever will.
How can you be so sure?
After all, you don't
know me well enough
to make a comparison.
I don't want
to know you well enough.
And if you want
to keep working with me
I suggest you stick to business.
I'm sorry, Major.
I didn't mean any harm.
I was only making conversation.
Damar, set another target.
We'll test our new weapon
as soon as the Major's ready.
Let's see if we can't
work out our problems
at least the ones we're
having with the disruptor.
This is a standard issue
Cardassian
phase-disruptor rifle.
It has a 4.7 megajoule
power capacity
three-millisecond recharge,
two beam settings.
How do you know so much
about Cardassian weapons?
We captured a lot of them
during the occupation.
It's a good weapon...
solid, simple.
You can drag it through the mud
and it'll still fire.
Now, this... this is
an entirely different animal.
Federation standard issue.
It's a little less powerful
but it's got
a lot more options.
16 beam settings.
Fully autonomous...
recharge...
multiple target acquisition...
gyro stabilized, the works.
It's, um, a little
more complicated
so it's not
as good a field weapon.
Too many things
can go wrong with it.
I can see why my father
likes having you around.
I think, um...
you should stick
with the Cardassian rifle.
It's smaller, easier to use,
and if we get boarded
I don't want you
to have to think too much
about the weapon you're using.
You don't like my father
very much, do you?
No.
I don't.
I understand.
He did some very bad things
during the occupation.
Yes, he did.
It bothers him, you know.
Does it?
Very much.
He talks about it sometimes.
He'd never admit it
to anyone else
but he thinks
the occupation was a mistake.
Somehow I don't think
he'd say that
if the Cardassians had won.
Maybe not.
But maybe losing made
him a better person.
Well, then a lot
of innocent people died
for his education.
I... I know.
I think about that a lot.
But when I look at my father
I have a hard time
seeing a murderer.
And when I look at him
I have a hard time
seeing anything else.
You're his daughter.
My father says
that the two of you
have a lot in common.
That you both did things
during the war that you regret.
That's why he cares so much
about what you think of him.
Ziyal, what your father
wants from me
is forgiveness.
That's one thing
I can never give him.
Now...
I think we should concentrate
on getting you comfortable
with this weapon.
What about the Cardassian base
on the fourth moon of Rakal?
Mmm. It's subterranean.
It's much too fortified
to be a viable target
for a bird-of-prey.
It would take
a Vor'cha-class cruiser
to do any real damage.
How about the station
on Amleth Prime?
No, the Amleth system's located
inside an emission nebula.
The Klingon cloaking device
would be useless.
I know where they'll go next...
Loval.
That's on the other side
of the sector.
A long way
from the Cardassian fleet.
From what it says here
Loval is mainly
a civilian outpost
with a small
subspace relay station.
The Klingons have been going
after a lot bigger prizes.
What it says there
is not exactly true.
Loval is also
a weapons research installation,
which is supposed to be
a closely guarded secret.
Now, considering the targets
the Klingons have hit so far
I think we've underestimated
their intelligence network.
Sounds like a choice target.
Loval it is.
The question is...
even if we're right,
can we stop them?
All we need is one good shot
with the new disruptor.
Which won't be easy to get,
considering they'll be cloaked.
We don't have to find them.
We have to make them come to us.
Lure them in.
Make them think that we're
a helpless freighter.
We have to make them
think... that we have
valuable cargo aboard.
How does refined
dilithium crystal sound?
I can get Damar to modify
the subspace transceiver array
to emit a false
dilithium signal.
Now, if I know the Klingons
they'll lock
their tractor beam on us
and try to take our cargo.
And we'll have a little surprise
waiting for them.
Yes.
Not bad.
I told you
we make a good team, Major.
You are as insightful a woman
as you are intriguing.
I thought we agreed
to keep this
strictly business.
Major, is it my imagination
or do you have a hard time
accepting compliments?
I have a hard time accepting
compliments from you.
Well, I'll try
to restrain my enthusiasm
but I can't make you
any promises.
We better get to Loval
before the Klingons do.
Damar.
Sir?
Set a course for Loval.
Maximum warp.
Aye, sir.
Loval system
within scanning range, sir.
Any sign of them?
No, sir.
If they're not there now
they'll be there soon enough.
Begin modifications to the
subspace transceiver array.
We soldiers spend
a lot of time waiting
don't we, Major?
It's not easy to keep
your mind from drifting.
I don't usually have any
trouble concentrating
unless I'm being distracted.
Lately, when my mind wanders
I find myself thinking
more and more about...
Gul Marratt.
Do you know him?
Very dashing.
One of Cardassia's
rising stars...
graduate of the Cardassian
Military Academy...
smooth-talking junior member
of the Detapa Council...
and like your friend Shakaar...
quite a ladies' man.
Especially
with other officers' wives.
Including yours?
Mmm.
A year ago, he wouldn't
have dared, but now...
I think the first thing I do
when I'm restored to power
will be to demote him.
Assign him to the Cardassian
Embassy on Breen.
I hear it's bitter cold
on Breen.
And we Cardassians
do despise the cold.
Sir.
I've got something.
On screen.
Well, Major...
it seems fate has smiled
on our little plan.
They're scanning us.
Good.
Let's hope they take the bait.
Sir, they've locked
their disruptors on us.
They haven't fired.
Which means they could be
interested in our cargo.
They're hailing us, sir.
Demanding our surrender.
They're interested.
Now let's see if you
can make them bite.
On screen.
Identify yourself.
I'm Gul Dukat
Commander of the Cardassian
Freighter Groumall.
Who are you?
What is your cargo
and destination?
We are carrying replicator
and transporter parts
to the Dopa system.
You're lying!
I assure you, Captain...
I'm confiscating your ship
and its cargo.
On whose authority?
On the authority
of the Klingon Empire
and the disruptors
I have pointed at your vessel.
Convincing, wasn't I?
I'll let you know.
They've locked
their tractor beam on us.
Wait for my signal.
Wait...
Open the cargo bay doors.
Doors opening.
Fire.
We've breached their hull.
Their impulse engines are down.
They're adrift.
Excellent.
They're re-locking
their disruptors on us.
All power
to forward shields.
Damage?
Both shields are down
to 20 percent!
We can't sustain another hit!
I think it's time to improvise!
I want all power
to the disruptors, now!
You, get down
to the weapons room
and find out
what's taking them so long.
Major!
Just give me a minute.
Hurry, Major.
Quiet.
I need to concentrate.
Lock target.
Prepare to fire.
You are a magician, Major.
There's nothing magical
about it.
Not when you know
Klingon transporter codes.
It worked.
All our people are here
and all 36 Klingons
are on the freighter.
Oh, I can just imagine
that Klingon Captain
explaining this
to his superiors.
He won't get the opportunity.
Was that necessary?
You're the terrorist.
You tell me.
Weapons secured, sir.
Excellent.
So is Engineering.
Well done.
Well, Major...
quite a prize we've taken.
The first Klingon bird-of-prey
ever to be captured
by Cardassia.
I think I just found
a bigger prize.
It looks like we've got
the target priorities
of all Klingon raiders
in Cardassian space.
Ha!
I'll contact Central Command
and inform them of our success.
I think I'll request
my Legate title be reinstated
effective immediately.
Get me Central Command.
No, on second thought...
this is too important for them.
I want to speak to the Chairman
of the Detapa Council himself
on a secure channel.
I can't do that from here, sir.
The communication terminals
on the Bridge are down.
But I could reroute it
to the Captain's quarters.
Good. Do so.
Then make the repairs.
I want this ship
fully operational
as soon as possible.
Aye, sir.
Ziyal, do you see
the phase compensator
in the backup plasma manifold?
What's it look like?
Perhaps I should go help her.
Klingon technology is...
Odd. Good idea.
Hang on, Ziyal.
Help's on the way.
Understood.
You know something, Dukat.
These computer logs
are even more valuable
than I thought.
They contain status reports
from Klingon ships and outposts
throughout Cardassian space.
With information like this,
Cardassia could launch a major
counterattack
against the Klingons.
They could
but they won't.
Why not?
The Detapa Council
has something else in mind.
They've ordered me not
to engage the Klingons
in any further conflict.
The Council is looking
for a diplomatic solution.
They've ordered me
to return to Cardassia Prime
to resume my...
post as Military Advisor.
Well, I thought
that's what you wanted.
It was.
But what is the point
of being a military advisor
to a government
that won't fight?
Well, you can change
their minds.
Convince your fellow Cardassians
to go on the offensive.
Nah, I'd be wasting my breath.
They wouldn't listen to me.
No one wants to fight.
There was a time
when the mere mention
of my race inspired fear.
And now...
we're a beaten people.
Afraid to fight back
because we don't want to lose
what little is left.
That's not the Cardassians
I know.
What Cardassians?
Don't you see, Major?
They're paralyzed.
They're beaten and defeated.
I am the only Cardassian left
and if no one else will stand
against the Klingons...
I will.
Look, Dukat,
I know you're angry
but maybe you ought to think
about what you're proposing.
I mean, you can't go to war
against the whole Klingon Empire
with one bird-of-prey.
Why not?
Your people fought
against us for 50 years
with much less sophisticated
weaponry than this
and you beat us.
It's not the same.
The Bajoran people were united.
We were all fighting
for the same goal.
You and your crew
would be out there alone.
Maybe at first,
but perhaps our actions
would inspire others
to join the struggle.
It's not that easy, Dukat.
I know...
which is why I need you.
Me?
Who else?
You know how to organize
a resistance cell
you're an expert
in terrorist tactics
you have close ties
with Bajoran
and Federation officials
and besides all that,
it would give you a chance
to do what you were meant to do.
No, thanks.
I've already got a job.
Oh! What do you mean?
On that space station?
We both know your talents
are being wasted there.
Coordinating docking assignments
and leading training exercises.
On Deep Space 9,
you're nothing but a bureaucrat.
An administrator.
If you come with me,
you can be a soldier again.
Think about it, Major...
the chance to fight
against a superior foe
in a righteous cause.
To protect a defeated
and broken people
from a cruel aggressor.
You know as well as I do
that, if Cardassia falls
Bajor is next.
Help me stop the Klingons
before you become
their next target.
You're really serious
about this.
Absolutely!
Look, Major,
I'm not asking you to like me
or to be my friend.
I'm asking you to join me.
To fight at my side.
You know
what I'm doing is right
and it's what you
want to do as well.
I know that our past
makes it difficult
for you to accept me
as an ally.
I also know that every fiber
of your being
is telling you
to say "no, no, no"
but somewhere,
I know there's a "yes."
You need to listen
to that "yes."
Not for my sake,
not for Cardassia's
not even for Bajor's...
but for your sake.
We've completed repairs
on the navigation system
and the cloaking device.
Good. We'll leave
as soon as you have it on line.
Think about it, Major.
Think about the possibilities.
Nerys.
I want to show you something.
Go ahead, attack me.
What are you talking about?
It's okay.
I know what I'm doing.
Damar showed me a good trick.
Try to stab me with the knife.
Guess it wasn't
such a good trick.
The best way
to survive a knife fight
is to never get in one.
If I'm going to help my father
I have to be prepared
for anything.
Show me what you did.
Please.
I know I have a lot to learn.
I have been practicing
with the disruptor rifle
but I need to know
how to defend myself
in hand-to-hand combat.
I was lucky not to have to fight
when we boarded this ship.
I may not be so lucky next time.
Chances are, you won't be.
Fighting the Klingons
is going to take more
than knowing how to fire a rifle
or use a knife.
You have to learn
to be ruthless.
to hate the Klingons...
even more
than you hated the Breen.
Whatever it takes, I will do it
but I'm going to need your help.
You're right.
You do need my help.
I... am disappointed, Major.
But not surprised.
Tell me...
were you even tempted?
Not really.
Hmm.
I thought I was so eloquent.
You had your moments
but the fact of the matter is
I've already been
where you're going.
I've lived the life
you're choosing...
fighting hit-and-run,
always outgunned
living on hate
and adrenaline...
it's not much of a life.
And it eats away at you
so that every day a
little bit of you dies.
Very inspiring, Major.
But I don't have
any choice in this...
no more than you had
when you fought against us.
No, I don't suppose you do.
Hmm.
Well... all that's left
is for you to wish me luck.
That's not quite all.
There's still Ziyal.
What about her?
The life you're choosing
isn't for her.
She deserves better.
She deserves to be
with her father.
You taught me that.
I love her.
I know you do
and that's why you've got
to let her go.
Go? Where?
She's not welcome
on Cardassia or Bajor.
This is the only place
she belongs.
That's not true.
She could come
to Deep Space 9 with me.
Are you serious?
She's a remarkable young woman.
I'll make sure she's okay.
Why?
Why do you care so much?
Because she reminds me
of myself...
and I don't want her to go
through what I went through
and neither do you.
Captain, a Klingon bird-of-prey
just de-cloaked off the station.
On screen.
They're hailing us.
Let's find out what they want.
Sir, it's Gul Dukat.
On a Klingon ship?
He's asking permission
to dock.
When this is all over,
I'll come back for you.
I promise you that.
I know you will.
Major...
I'll take good care of her.
I know.
Well, Major, it appears
that whether you like it or not
our lives have become
deeply intertwined.
That really pleases you,
doesn't it?
Pleases me?
Major, it gives me
reason to live.
Come.
I'll show you to your quarters.
Welcome back, Major.
Odo, this is Tora Ziyal.
Gul Dukat's daughter.
She going to be living here
on the station with us...
for a while.
Ah.
I'll tell you all about it.
I certainly hope so.