( grunting )
E-cha.
Movek.
Okay...
I see your point.
The mek'leth
definitely has its advantages,
but I still think
the bat'leth,
with its longer reach,
is usually
the deciding factor.
That is a classic argument.
However, I find using a large
and intimidating weapon
like the bat'leth
often leads to overconfidence.
So you think
that I was overconfident.
You were overconfident.
You thought by distracting me
with your outfit,
you would gain an advantage.
My outfit.
Um...
I thought that...
I mean, I only assumed that...
You thought that I
wore this for you.
Talk about
overconfidence.
Worf...
E-cha.
Movek.
But in my own defense,
you do try your own
tactics of distraction
with all that shouting
and growling you do.
I'm only vocalizing my...
Odo to Worf.
Worf here.
Please report
to Airlock 5, Commander.
There's an intoxicated
Klingon here
who's demanding to see you.
I'm on my way.
Computer, exit.
Stay back!
You miserable koruts!
Easy!
None of us koruts
is going to hurt you.
Kurn!
Worf.
I knew you'd come.
He is my brother.
The sons of Mogh reunited
for one last time.
Where have you been?
I have tried to
contact you for months.
Well, I'm here now...
but not for long.
Soon there will be
only one son of Mogh.
I came for Mauk-to'Vor.
What?
Yes, Brother.
I want you to kill me.
( snoring )
( grunting )
( yelling )
Guard!
Something for my head!
You are not in
the holding cell.
You're in my quarters.
For your head.
Soft...
comfortable...
just like the rest
of these quarters.
No one would ever suspect
a warrior lives here.
It serves me.
Always defending the Federation.
Tell me, Worf, does Starfleet
ever make mistakes,
even in their furniture?
Kurn, where have you been?
It has been four months
since your last message.
I've been overseeing the end
of a once-proud House.
Perhaps you've heard of it.
It was called
the House of Mogh.
I know what has happened.
I regret that,
by opposing Gowron,
I have brought disgrace
to our family.
You regret?
What's next, Worf?
Do you want to apologize to me?
Express your sympathy?
How many human weaknesses
will you display?
I do not apologize
for what I have done.
I could not join Gowron
in his war with Cardassia
or the Federation.
It would've been dishonorable.
Oh, so, in avoiding dishonor
for yourself,
you've brought it down
on the rest of your family.
What a noble act.
How selfless.
I will not debate this
with you, Kurn.
What is done is done.
For you, it's done--
you and your comfortable
Federation life,
your glorious Starfleet career--
but not for me.
Our family had a seat
on the High Council.
We were feared
by our enemies,
respected
by our friends.
It was even said
that if Gowron died,
the leadership of the Council
might be passed to someone
from the House of Mogh.
Then you chose to side
with the Federation
against the Empire.
Gowron took our ships,
our land,
our seat on the Council,
everything.
Kurn, I know
this has been difficult for you.
What do you know?
Did you watch as Gowron's men
seized our land
and stripped our family
of its name?
Did you have to endure
the humiliation
of being ejected
from the High Council
in front of
the Emperor himself?
No. You chose to stay here,
safe, comfortable, secure.
You have everything you want,
and I have nothing,
not even my honor,
but you can
give that back to me.
By killing you?
I'm already dead
to our people,
and so are you,
but you don't care.
I have never asked you
for anything,
but you took away my honor,
and only you
can give it back.
So now I am asking you
for Mauk-to'Vor.
Is an honorable death
too much to ask from my brother?
O'BRIEN:
Operations Log,
Stardate 49556.2.
Major Kira and I are
returning to the station
after completing
our inspection tour
of the Bajoran colonies
along the Cardassian border.
This is the Federation
Runabout Yukon
requesting permission
to enter Bajoran space.
This is Bajoran control.
Please transmit
your identification code
and flight plan.
Acknowledged.
Major.
Major!
Yes? What?
Sorry, Major.
It's just
we're almost home.
Oh, thanks.
Almost home?
How long have
I been asleep?
Seven hours.
I don't get seven hours
sleep at the station.
Must be the company.
Bajoran Control to Yukon.
You are cleared
to enter the system
and proceed to Deep Space 9.
Thank you.
( yawning )
Oh, I am so hungry,
I could even eat
Quark's food.
Let's not get crazy.
If you really want
some good--
What was that?
Some kind
of high-energy discharge.
It was pretty close.
Only 5,000 kilometers
from here.
Just outside Bajoran space.
Elevated tachyon readings,
subspace shock waves.
Looks like
a cloaked ship exploded.
There's no debris.
No residual warp fields.
Well, something
exploded.
Let's take a closer look.
Bring us to 500 meters
from those coordinates.
Approaching the coordinates.
I'm not seeing any signs of...
Wait a minute.
I'm picking up
another tachyon surge.
A ship's de-cloaking
directly ahead of us.
KLINGON:
Federation vessel.
This is the Imperial
Klingon Ship Korinar.
We are engaged in military
exercises in this area.
You will alter course
and return to Bajoran space
immediately.
This is Major
Kira Nerys.
We're investigating an explosion
which happened
at these coordinates--
You have been given a warning
according
to interstellar agreements.
You will not receive another.
They've locked their
disruptors onto us, Major.
Take us home, Chief.
But keep scanning
the coordinates
of that explosion.
There's a lot more
going on out here
than just military exercises.
Quark, have you seen Worf?
He was supposed to meet me
in the holosuite
five minutes ago.
As if you're
never late.
Worf is never late.
In fact, he grumbles at me
if I'm two minutes
behind schedule.
Well, I haven't seen him
since this morning,
and if he can't
at least be civil,
I don't care to see
him in my bar again.
It's just his way.
It's nothing personal, Quark.
No.
This was more than
his standard rudeness.
He came in here, ordered
some Klingon incense
and nearly threw me across
the bar when I tried
to give him some
replicated incense.
What kind of Klingon incense?
Something called
adanji.
What would he want
with adanji?
Why? Is there something
special about adanji?
That does it.
I'm going to stop talking
to the customers.
You have been wronged
in this life.
There is nothing left here
for you.
No honor...
no future.
Mmm...
I wish to reclaim my honor
in the next life.
I am ready to cross
the River of Blood
and enter Sto-Vo-Kor.
Commander.
Odo, yesterday you called
Worf to the airlock
to see some Klingon.
That's right.
Who was it?
His name is Kurn.
It turns out
he's Worf's brother.
Worf's brother.
Oh, my God.
Dax to Worf.
Computer, locate
Commander Worf.
Commander Worf
is in his quarters.
Is he alone?
Negative.
Captain Kurn is with him.
Come on.
May this blade speed you
on your journey.
Good-bye, my brother.
Good... bye.
( grunting )
( yells )
Dax to Ops.
Emergency transport.
Two to the Infirmary.
This is not your concern!
It is a private matter!
I doubt Captain Sisko
would agree.
You'd better hope
he lives, Commander.
If not, you'll be charged
with murder.
Kurn's going to make it.
Julian said he'll be up
on his feet by tomorrow morning.
Good. Mr. Worf,
I want you to tell me
why I shouldn't put you on
the next transport out of here.
You are well within
your right to do so.
I'm not talking
about my rights.
Answer my question.
Captain, I do not
have an answer.
Sir, I realize my actions
were in violation of
Starfleet regulations--
Regulations? We're not
talking about some obscure
technicality, Mr. Worf.
You tried to commit
premeditated murder.
Benjamin, it wasn't murder.
Worf and Kurn were performing
a Mauk-to'Vor ritual.
It's part of Klingon belief
that when--
At the moment, I don't give
a damn about Klingon beliefs,
rituals or custom!
Now, I have given you both
a lot of leeway
when it comes to following
Klingon traditions,
but in case you haven't noticed,
this is not a Klingon station,
and those are not Klingon
uniforms you're wearing.
There is a limit
to how far I'll go
to accommodate cultural
diversity among my officers,
and you've just reached it!
When your brother is released
from the Infirmary,
you better find another way
to settle your family problems.
Is that clear?!
Captain, it may not
be possible--
Uh, it's clear.
There are definitely
other possibilities for Kurn.
This will never happen again.
You're damned right it won't!
Now, both of you-- get out!
What do you make of it, Chief?
From these
magnetic flux readings,
the energy discharge we detected
could have been caused
by the destruction
of a cloaked target drone.
Which would support the
story about conducting
military maneuvers.
O'BRIEN: On the other hand,
this type of explosion
could also have been caused
by an accidental
warp nacelle inversion.
Or a blown plasma conduit
or a dozen other things.
The bottom line is there's
no way to be certain
from these readings.
The larger question is:
What are these Klingons up to?
Whatever it is,
they're doing it
awfully close
to Bajoran space.
And they're very touchy
about it.
One thing I've had enough of
is tiptoeing
around the Klingons.
Take the Defiant
and run a sensor sweep
of those coordinates.
And if I run
into the Klingons?
Tell them that the ship
is conducting military exercises
according
to interstellar agreements.
Understood.
Should I take Worf?
I don't want Worf anywhere near
other Klingons right now.
Keep him informed
of what's going on,
but under no circumstances
is he to accompany you.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Sir...
Don't say it, Chief.
I've already got
one officer defending Worf.
I don't need two.
He's stabilized.
I can revive him
at any time.
Wake him.
I'll be just outside
if you need me.
I...
am... alive?
Yes.
Commander Dax realized
what we were doing
and she had you beamed
to the Infirmary.
I was looking forward
to being in Sto-Vo-Kor.
( sighs )
I was hoping
to see Father there.
He still awaits you,
but it is not yet time
for you to join him.
And I suppose
you will decide
when that time has come.
It is not for me
to make that choice.
Why not?
You chose not to complete
the Mauk-to'Vor ritual.
It was not my decision.
It was Dax and Odo
that prevented...
Did you
fight them?
Did you threaten
to kill them both
if they interfered?
And are you standing here now
with the mevak dagger,
ready to slit my throat
and bring me the death
I deserve?
No.
For a moment,
in your quarters,
during the ritual...
you were Klingon.
But your Federation life
has claimed you again,
and now
it is claiming me as well.
I have no life.
I have no death.
Whatever is to become of me
is up to you.
( door chimes )
Enter.
What can I do for you,
Commander?
I wanted to apologize.
I interfered
in a family matter,
and if I caused you
and your brother
any further dishonor,
I'm sorry.
You were following
your conscience.
That is an honorable motive.
Not from a Klingon
point of view.
You are not Klingon.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
No.
Okay.
Commander.
There is the question
of what to do next.
Right.
Do you have any ideas?
None.
Well, in the short term,
there's no reason
why your brother can't stay here
on the station.
If Kurn is to remain
on the station,
he will need
tasks to perform.
A job.
What about security?
It worked for one
Klingon officer I know.
Yes, but I doubt Kurn
would be interested
in joining Starfleet.
Well, there is another
security force on the station.
Well, your brother's had
an interesting career
with the Klingon Defense Forces,
Mr. Worf.
I have just one question:
Does he know how to use
the stun setting
on a disruptor?
Non-lethal skills are not
valued in the Empire.
They are among my deputies.
And if your brother is going
to be a member of my detachment,
he's going to have to make some
adjustments in his thinking.
He will.
You're certain
of that?
I would not be asking you
to consider him if I were not.
I can appreciate how difficult
it must be for you
to be asking for a favor,
especially from me.
Very well.
Have Kurn report here
tomorrow morning.
I am indebted to you.
Yes, you are.
And, Mr. Worf?
You'll find I'm a man
who collects on his debts.
This container
is not on your manifest.
It must be a clerical error.
I apologize.
Open it.
This is a message
from Starfleet Command
requesting an update
on our defense systems.
I'd say your brother's
doing well, Commander.
He's been on the job
six hours,
he's only killed
four Boslics so far.
Hmm.
Kira's right.
You do need
a sense of humor.
He's quite good, actually.
A little stern, but he never
steps over the line.
I'm finding him to be
a pleasant surprise.
I am...
gratified to hear that.
I'm sure you are.
Well, thanks for
the report, Commander.
I'll give it my
immediate attention.
Brother.
Kurn.
I hate this uniform.
I understand.
The transition will probably
be difficult for some time.
No, that's not
what I mean.
I have accepted
the transition.
I am a Bajoran
security officer.
The uniform is simply
uncomfortable.
I see.
But I will
get used to it.
You need not concern
yourself with me, Brother.
I won't disgrace you.
I never doubted it.
Carry on.
The same thing, Major.
High concentrations
of tachyons,
subspace distortions
and magneton traces.
Some cloaked ships
definitely passed
through this area in
the last 24 hours.
They're getting close
to violating Bajoran space,
but they're never
crossing the line.
I've never known Klingons
to be this fastidious
when it comes to
respecting borders.
Especially when
they're cloaked.
Something's wrong here.
( alarm blaring )
O'BRIEN:
That's a Vor'cha-class cruiser.
Stand by shields
and phasers.
They've been damaged.
There's a massive hull breach
in their port quarter.
Main power's failing.
Casualties?
It's hard to tell through
all this radiation.
Open a channel.
Channel open.
This is Major Kira Nerys
on the USS Defiant
to unidentified Klingon vessel.
Do you require assistance?
This is IKS Drovana
to USS Defiant.
We do not require assistance
at this time.
Do not approach us.
Understood, Drovana.
Defiant out.
They're losing emergency power.
Why aren't the other
Klingon ships helping them?
Maybe they don't want to give
away their positions.
Maybe they're busy
doing something that
can't be interrupted.
Something that blew a hole
the size of a house
in a Vor'cha-class cruiser.
Incoming transmission.
Drovana to Defiant.
We need access
to your medical facilities.
Our medical facilities
are extremely limited.
If you wish, we can tow you
to Deep Space 9.
Stand by.
Defiant, your offer
is accepted.
Odo to Worf.
Worf here.
We need you in the Infirmary,
Commander.
Your brother's
been seriously injured.
On my way.
What happened?
Kurn found a container
of contraband
in the lower hold
of the Boslic ship.
When he confronted
their Captain,
the man pulled out
a disruptor pistol
and then Kurn
let himself get shot.
Let himself?
Kurn is a trained
Klingon warrior.
He could have disarmed
the Boslic
without breaking a sweat,
but he just stood there,
let the man pull out
his weapon, aim and fire.
The only thing that saved him
was the man was so frightened
his hand was shaking.
He'll be all right... again.
Good.
A man with a death wish is
a danger not only to himself,
but to the rest
of his team.
Kurn's days
as a security officer are over.
Would you like
to see him?
Yes.
Thank you, Doctor.
How do you feel?
Like a man who is
tired of waking up
and seeing
a human doctor's face.
I thought we had agreed
that you would try to make...
Worf...
I don't want
to talk anymore.
It's not Klingon.
You're the elder brother.
You tell me what to do
and I'll do it.
My life is in your hands.
BASHIR:
Well, so far,
there's nothing unusual
about any
of their casualties.
I've treated 15 cases of
severe radiation burns,
seven thoracic perforation
traumas caused by shrapnel,
and 23
decompression-related injuries.
All just what you'd expect
following an explosion
on a starship.
SISKO:
Do you have any idea
what caused the explosion?
Well, the radiation burns
were the result of exposure
to gamma rays.
My guess is they were hit
by a photon torpedo.
A torpedo?
From the fracture
pattern of the damage,
I'd say something exploded
about ten kilometers
off their port quarter.
But torpedoes
leave ion trails,
and the Defiant
didn't pick up any
in the vicinity.
And the Drovana
was cloaked.
Even Klingon torpedoes
can't track vessels
operating under cloak.
WORF:
Mines.
They hit a mine.
That's why there
weren't any ion trails.
And cloaked mines
can't be detected
by any known sensor array.
But there have been
at least a dozen ships
moving in and out of that system
since the explosion.
Why haven't they
struck any mines?
Well, the type of mine
currently used by the Klingons
remains dormant
until it is armed
by a coded
subspace signal.
So, the mine that
damaged the Drovana
must have malfunctioned
or been set off prematurely.
If we're right, there could be
thousands of mines
out there right now, and we'd
have no way of knowing it.
Mining a star system
is an act of war.
I didn't think the Klingons
were ready for that.
At the moment,
we can't even prove
these mines exist,
but if war comes,
the Klingons would be able
to cut off Deep Space 9
and the entire
Bajoran system.
How do we find
these mines?
Unless we know
their coordinates,
there's no way to find them
until we run into one.
Then we better get
those coordinates.
The place to
get them is docked at
Upper Pylon 3 right now.
The only question is how.
I have an idea.
You want me to turn
against my own people?
Will my dishonor never end?
It is their actions
that are dishonorable.
Secretly mining star systems
is not the act of warriors.
They behave like...
like Romulan cowards.
Is that how you
rationalize this--
by calling your people cowards
so you can be a hero?
Kurn, let me ask you this.
Do you agree
with what has happened
between the Empire
and the Federation?
It is not my place
to criticize--
Answer the question!
No. I opposed the decision
to break the treaty
but I was overruled
in Council.
Why did you oppose the decision?
Because Gowron
underestimates the Federation.
He thinks they're soft, weak,
but he is wrong.
Sooner or later,
there will be war.
A war the Empire may lose.
Yes.
You know that
mining this system
is just the beginning.
If we do nothing,
it will only encourage Gowron
to continue thinking
of the Federation as weak.
Eventually, he will attack,
and that will be
the end of the Empire.
That is why you must join me
on this mission.
Not for my honor,
and not for the Federation,
but to prevent the Empire
from being destroyed
in a war they cannot win.
Our people have turned
their backs on us,
but we have not turned
our backs on them.
Let it be the sons
of Mogh, side by side,
saving our people.
Do this with me.
There. Very ugly.
Well, uglier, that is.
Joke.
I got it.
Well, this will
temporarily alter
your DNA signature
to match one of
our friends over there.
Should be good enough
to pass a cursory test.
How long will it last?
About four hours.
That should be
sufficient.
Kurn.
Kurn?
Yes, Doctor?
Please take a seat.
The deployment
plan for the mines
should be in the
defense system database.
I have found
the main file directory.
No, no. Ignore it.
It's a security
procedure
the High Council
instituted
three months ago.
False directories,
files,
entire databases
of disinformation
designed for spies
to steal.
Here's the real database.
Can you access
the deployment plan?
My security codes
have been changed
but not all of them.
Yes.
( door opens )
You two...
what are you doing?
We're running a diagnostic
of the computer core.
There have been power
fluctuations in the
navigational control system.
I've not been informed
of any computer problems.
Perhaps you have
not been tending
to your duties.
I do not know you.
What is your name?
I am Commander Sorval
son of M'tokra.
How long have you been
aboard, Commander?
I will not be questioned
by a Lieutenant
who should be cleaning
my quarters.
Leave us, or I shall
have you stripped of rank
and sent home
in a transport.
My words were
ill-chosen, Commander.
Perhaps I can help you
with your investigation.
That will not be necessary.
All we require...
You did not have to do that.
He was backing down.
He was going to kill you.
We must hurry.
The disruptor blast will
alert the security sensors.
He was a warrior,
doing his duty,
defending the Empire
and I killed him.
My dishonor is complete.
Since we now have the detonation
codes for each mine,
we can set them off individually
or all at once.
Thank you,
Commander. Major?
We'll take care of it.
Congratulations,
Mr. Worf.
You did an
excellent job.
That goes for
your brother, too.
Thank you, sir.
You don't seem very pleased.
I am still troubled by the death
of that Klingon officer.
Your report said
it was self-defense.
That is not the point.
I should have seen
what he was going to do.
What do you mean?
From the way
you described it,
he was standing so close to you
you couldn't have seen
the knife in his hand.
He decided to kill me
while I was looking him
right in the eyes,
and I never saw it.
But Kurn did,
and he was three meters away.
Worf, I don't think
you can tell
someone's going to kill you
by looking at them.
A Klingon can.
It is an instinct.
The ability
to look someone in the eyes
and see the decision to kill.
An instinct I no longer have.
Kurn was right.
I have lived
with humans so long,
I no longer think
like a Klingon.
For a long time,
I have tried
to walk the line between
the Empire and the Federation.
I told myself
I could live in either world,
that it was my choice.
But the truth is,
I cannot go back to the Empire.
Do you want to go back?
I had always hoped
that one day the House of Mogh
would reclaim its rightful place
and that I would return.
But now I know
that even if I did,
I have no place there.
This is all I have.
Is that enough?
It will have to be.
But my brother
does not even have this.
For him, there is no future
without the Empire--
no life.
It sounds like you're thinking
of carrying out the
Mauk-to'Vor ritual again.
No. I was able
to do it once
by telling myself it was
an honorable Klingon ritual,
but now I cannot help
but think of it as humans do...
as murder.
What if there was a way
for you to kill your brother...
without killing him?
We're ready, Major.
Open a channel.
This is the USS Defiant
to all Klingon vessels
near the Bajoran system.
We are preparing
to destroy your minefield.
I suggest you leave immediately.
This is your only warning.
Anything?
Nothing. If they're out there,
they're keeping quiet.
Well, they're out
there all right,
and I think we'll
be seeing them fairly soon.
Prepare to detonate the mine
in grid 21 alpha.
Ready, sir.
Send out the code.
Still nothing, Major.
Well, we can't say
we didn't warn them.
Detonate all the mines
in grids 22 alpha
through 47 gamma.
Aye, sir.
Just like flushing quail.
They're setting course...
327 mark 215.
Back to the Klingon Empire.
Let's see
how many other birds
we can flush out of here.
Why is it that suicide
is considered
a dishonorable death, Worf?
Shouldn't a warrior
have the right
to decide
when his time has come?
If you die by
your own hand,
you will not travel
across the River of Blood
and enter Sto-Vo-Kor.
Even if I got cast down
into the Underworld,
at least I'd be
with other Klingons,
even though they are
the dishonored dead.
Put down the disruptor.
Do you know what
my one regret is, Worf?
That we weren't raised together.
In the Empire, on Earth--
it wouldn't have mattered
but the sons of Mogh should
have never been separated.
On that...
we both agree.
But that is
the past,
and a warrior
should look to the future.
And in the future,
you should not be
burdened by my dishonor.
You are not a burden.
I have never
understood you, Worf.
But I do know this.
In your own way...
you are an honorable man.
And you will be
an honorable man again...
but not as my brother.
How long will
the procedure take?
Well, wiping his memory
will be relatively simple--
say, an hour--
but changing
his genetic coding,
combined with surgically
altering his features,
will take at least
another five hours.
What will he remember?
He'll know
he's a Klingon
and how to speak
the language
and virtually everything
he needs to know
in order to survive--
except who he is.
And that's the first
question he'll ask.
"Who am I?"
Do you have an answer?
There is a man
named Noggra,
a friend of our father's.
He will be arriving
in a few hours.
He has agreed
to provide Kurn
with a new identity
and a new family.
He will supply Kurn
with all the answers
he needs.
Are you absolutely
certain about this, Worf?
Once I've erased
his memory engrams,
it'll be almost impossible
to restore them.
He won't remember you
or anything about
his real life.
It is the only way.
You may begin.
Prep him for surgery.
Rodek.
Can you hear me?
Rodek!
( groaning )
Where..?
Where am I?
On a Federation space station.
Our shuttle was damaged.
You were hit
by a plasma discharge.
I don't remember being...
on a shuttle.
In fact, I don't
remember anything.
The plasma discharge
damaged your hippocampus.
You're suffering from
a severe form of amnesia.
I'm afraid you may never regain
all of your memory.
Who am I?
NOGGRA:
Your name is Rodek.
You are my son.
You're part
of the House of Noggra,
a small but proud family.
So don't worry.
I will teach you all
that you have forgotten
when we get home.
I understand, Father.
Who are you?
I am Worf.
Are you part
of my family?
I have no family.