Department heads
prepare reports
for tomorrow's briefing.
All hands dismissed.
I'd say that was
a successful mission.
Five days in the Gamma Quadrant
and no sign of the Jem'Hadar.
Commander...
during our maneuvers
through that asteroid belt
on the Kar-telos system
I noticed the Defiant
felt a little... sluggish
when turning hard aport.
The inertial
dampening generators
may need to be realigned.
I'll begin drawing up
a schedule immediately.
And while we're at it,
we should recalibrate
the targeting scanners
and check the EPS relays.
O'Brien's going to be
a little disappointed.
He thought he finally
had the ship running smoothly.
Well, Chief O'Brien
has done an excellent job.
This is a fine ship.
But it is my duty
to keep her functioning
at peek proficiency.
Mister Worf... you're in love.
With the Defiant.
You exaggerate...
as usual.
I feel silly.
I like it.
It shows off your legs.
There you see...
your public has spoken.
Have fun.
What do you call this holosuite
program of yours again?
The Battle of Clontarf...
you, me and a thousand
stalwart Irish warriors
against a ravening
hoard of Vikings.
It's like the Battle of Britain
only with swords.
How come you get
to be High King?
I am a direct descendant
of King Brian Boru.
Besides...
it's my program.
I suppose that's only fair.
Oh...
I know exactly how you feel.
The Bajoran Time of Cleansing.
Can someone explain to me
why the Bajorans need
to abstain
from worldly pleasures
for an entire month?
I mean, it's not like
they're a bunch of hedonistic
holosuite-obsessed drunkards
to begin with.
No use moaning about it.
It hurts.
Who's that for?
Me.
It's one of Moogie's
home remedies.
Your ear?
Again?
That's disgusting.
You want to drive away
all the rest of my customers?
I feel dizzy.
What else is new?
Go wait on table seven.
Rom, you look terrible.
I think you better lie down.
I don't pay you to think.
I pay you to spin
the dabo wheel.
So get spinning.
But nobody's gambling.
How can they when you're not
at the wheel?
I really don't feel good.
Can't you see he's sick?
He needs to lie down.
Just because you happen to be
intimately acquainted with
Dr. Bashir's bedside manner
doesn't make you
a medical expert.
Brother, am I still standing?
What I do during my time off
is no business of yours.
If you don't get back
to work this instant
you're going to have
more time off
than you know what to do with.
The same goes for you.
Here.
Yes, Brother.
Aren't you going
to do something?
Of course,
I'm going to do something.
I'm going to dock his pay.
Briok, clean up this mess.
Oh...
Oh, this is one
stubborn infection.
How long have you had it?
Uh, a couple of weeks.
You mean to tell me
you've been walking around
with a seeping infection
of the tympanic membrane
for two weeks?
More like three, actually.
Rom! You could have died.
Another 48 hours
and you would have been
bidding for a new life
at the Divine Treasury.
I guess it's a good thing
I fainted when I did.
Why didn't you come
and see me sooner?
I couldn't.
I was busy.
I'm sure your brother
could have spared you
for half an hour.
It would have been
a violation of my contract...
paragraph 76, subsection three.
"Employees of Quark's Bar
and Holding Company
"are strictly prohibited from
leaving the work environment
"during business hours
"unless ordered to do so
by their employer.
"Any failure to comply
with this provision
will result in severe fines
and possible dismissal."
It's a standard provision
in all Ferengi labor contracts.
You mean, you don't get time off
even if you're sick?
It's all part of our...
generous employee
compensation package.
"No sick days, no vacations
no paid overtime."
It sounds to me like
you need a better contract.
There's no such thing.
All Ferengi labor
contracts are the same.
Well, that should do it.
But I want you to see me
first thing in the morning
for a follow-up.
It'll have to be
before the bar opens.
What you people need is a union.
A what?
You know, a trade guild
a collective bargaining
association, a union...
something to keep you
from being exploited.
You don't understand.
Ferengi workers don't want
to stop the exploitation.
We want to find a way
to become the exploiters.
Suit yourself.
But I don't see you
exploiting anyone.
Rom... how'd it go?
I'm okay.
Oh. Julian's a wonderful doctor.
Your brother should have
let you see him weeks ago.
It's not Quark's fault
that I got sick.
I forgot to get
my bimonthly ear scan.
And besides, I've probably
been getting too much oo-mox.
Really?
Who's the lucky female?
No female. Just me.
I'm...
sorry.
Sorry enough to do
something about it?
I... don't think
Julian would approve.
We could ask him.
All right, everyone...
gather around.
What now?
I have an announcement
to make.
I've just been going over
today's receipts
and it's not good.
The only thing this Bajoran
Cleansing Ritual has cleansed
is my profit margin.
So, starting tomorrow
everyone's salary
gets cut by a third.
No, no, that's not fair.
I'll talk to him.
It's either that
or fire half the staff.
Don't bother thanking me.
I can't afford a pay cut.
It's either
a pay cut or a layoff.
You decide.
All right, everyone,
let's get back to work.
I want this place cleaned up
and the lights off
in ten minutes.
Brother...
this isn't right.
You can't just cut
people's salaries
without warning.
Actually, I can.
And I have.
Now, why don't you concentrate
on keeping your hands
off your lobes
and leave the business
matters to me.
But once the Cleansing
Ritual is over
you'll restore
everyone's salary, right?
That depends on next
quarter's fiscal summation.
Brother, I'm asking you...
as a personal favor
to reconsider this pay cut.
Anything for you.
Um...
There.
I've reconsidered it.
My decision stands.
But, Brother...
Don't "Brother" me.
In this bar,
you're not my brother.
You're my employee.
And employees have no right
to question
the management's decisions.
I'm warning you.
If you don't rescind
the pay cuts...
you're going to regret it.
The only thing I regret
is not being an only child.
You know, I think I'm finally
getting the hang
of this mek'leth.
Don't you think?
It would seem so.
Then why haven't you told me?
A Klingon warrior
does not need the
praise of his teacher.
I'm not a Klingon warrior.
I'm a beautiful
and sensitive young woman
who thrives on...
What is it?
Listen.
Do not move.
Worf?
Isn't this your tooth sharpener?
This p'tak just
robbed my quarters.
Take him to a holding cell.
I'll need a statement.
And you will have one.
But what I want to know is
how such a security breach
was allowed to occur
in the first place!
Unfortunately,
these things happen.
They did not happen
on the Enterprise.
Really.
Well, let me see.
"Stardate 46235.7.
"Ferengi privateers,
led by DaiMon Lurin, boarded
"and seized control
of the Enterprise
"using two salvaged
Klingon birds-of-prey.
"Stardate 45349.1.
Berlinghoff Rasmussen
"a petty criminal
impersonating a scientist
"committed numerous
acts of theft
against the crew
of the Enterprise. "
Shall I continue?
That will not be necessary.
I know these incidents
are the exception
rather than the rule,
but if security breaches
like these could happen on
the flagship of the Federation
imagine the difficulty
of maintaining security
at an open port such as DS9.
I understand.
It is just that I find it...
irritating.
So do I.
But I'm afraid you're just
going to have to get used to it.
Attention, please.
Thank you all for coming.
I know that in the past,
I've always defended my brother
whenever he's taken a stance
that's proven unpopular
with the staff.
But I'm not going
to do that today.
You're not?
No. I'm not.
Quark's just using
the Cleansing Ritual...
to increase his profits
at our expense.
It isn't fair.
And we're not going to take it.
Since when?
Since... right now.
So what are we
going to do about it?
We're going to fight back
in the only way we can.
We're going to form a...
a...
A what?
We're going to form...
a union.
Are you insane?
You've just destroyed the lives
of every Ferengi in this room.
When the FCA finds out we've
even been talking of a...
a...
A union.
Don't say that word again.
We're in enough trouble
as it is.
The Ferengi Commerce Authority
doesn't have to hear about this.
If we all go back to work now
no one else has to know
this ever happened.
No, no!
It's too late for that.
The FCA has ears everywhere.
As soon as their lobes
get wind of this
we're all doomed!
All right!
So we're doomed.
FCA liquidators
will probably haunt us
for the rest of our lives.
But I say if they're
going to come after us
let's give them a good reason.
Every one of you...
Ferengi and non-Ferengi alike...
knows that the way
Quark treats us is unfair.
Frool, don't you
deserve a day off
when your back starts acting up?
Well, uh... I suppose.
And Grimp...
wouldn't you like
to take a paid vacation?
You're being ridiculous.
Answer the question.
It's not going to happen!
It won't happen
unless you make it happen.
We're Ferengi!
And when a Ferengi
sees an opportunity
what does he do?
He seizes it?
That's right!
And I, for one,
intend to grab it.
We've been exploited
long enough.
It's time to be strong.
Take control of our lives.
Our dignity
and our profits!
Yes!
Strike a blow against Quark.
Yes.
Strike a blow against the FCA.
Yes!
Strike a blow
against exploitation!
Yes!
Are you with me?
Union!
Union! Union! Union! Union!
What you have there
is a sebaceous cyst.
I know it's a cyst,
but it's getting bigger.
There's nothing to worry about.
Dermatologically speaking,
you're perfectly healthy.
Oh, I'm perfectly healthy
except I've got
a disgusting cyst
on the back of my neck.
Now either I paint a nose,
eyes and mouth on it
and pretend I've got two heads
or you take it off.
Well, I'll get you some paint.
Julian, get it off me!
All right, all right.
But you know what they say:
Two heads are better than one.
Julian, I'm waiting.
Dr. Bashir
I'm glad you're in.
I need your help.
Is that ear acting up again?
My ear's fine.
I need some advice about...
unions.
Unions.
You said the other day
I should form a union, so I did.
Rom, I was speaking
theoretically.
And I've put
your theory into practice.
All of Quark's employees
have joined.
We're going to force Quark
to treat us better...
I hope.
A union, huh?
Good for you.
You know about unions?
Who do you think led
the Pennsylvania coal miners
during the anthracite
strike of 1902?
I have no idea.
Sean Aloysius O'Brien.
I didn't know that.
There's a lot of things
about my family you don't know.
11 months those mines
were closed
and they didn't open again
until all the miners'
demands were met.
You mean, we should force
Quark to close the bar.
Only as a last resort.
If he's reasonable
about your requests
there's no need to strike.
Quark reasonable?
Ha!
Unlikely.
You'll have to strike...
mark my words...
and when you do,
you'll have to be strong.
Just like Sean O'Brien.
Exactly.
You know, he had
the biggest funeral
in all of western Pennsylvania.
Funeral?
Hmm. They fished his body
out of the Allegheny River
a week before the strike ended.
32 bullets he had in him.
Or was it 34?
Well, he died a hero.
He was more than a hero.
He was a union man.
I see the problem now.
You've got a bad ODN relay here.
We'll have to replace
the whole unit.
How long will it take?
Two to three hours.
But after that,
it'll work like a charm.
Until the next time
it breaks down.
Well, that's the problem
when you combine
Cardassian, Bajoran
and Federation technology.
None of it was meant
to work together.
How do you tolerate
working in this environment?
Well, it's a lot easier
than working on the Enterprise.
Easier? The Enterprise never had
these kind of problems.
Tell me about it.
Have you any idea
how bored I used to get
sitting in the transporter room
waiting for something
to break down?
Here, I've half a dozen
new problems every day.
This station needs me.
Oh, do me a favor.
Hand me down the coil spanner?
Happy cleansing.
If this is
a surprise birthday party
you're a month late.
It's not a party.
We're the Guild of Restaurant
and Casino Employees
and we're here
to present our demands.
The Guild of Restaurant
and Casino Employees?
What's that supposed to be?
What does it sound like?
It sounds like...
like a union.
Exactly.
So you'd better take
our demands seriously.
"Increased pay...
"Shorter hours...
Paid sick leave..."
This is no joke.
Yes, it is.
And the fact that you
don't know that it is
is what makes it so funny.
Now get back to work
before I fire the lot of you.
You can't fire us.
Why not?
Because as of right now...
we're all on strike.
Yeah!
Thank you for not
patronizing Quark's.
Thanks very much.
Thank you for not
patronizing Quark's.
Thank you for not patronizing
Quark's.
Thank you for not
patronizing Quark's.
Thank you for not patronizing
Quark's.
I hope Rom's voice holds out.
I hope our latinum holds out.
Ahh...
You wanted to see me?
May I take your order, sir?
Quark, I'm in no mood for games.
There seems to be an opening
at the dabo table
or perhaps I might interest you
in some time in the holosuites.
Not again.
Are you carrying
a tricorder or anything
with a portable energy source?
What are you talking about?
I'm still working out the bugs
in these holographic waiters.
The Lissepian
who sold me the program
neglected to mention
that certain energy sources
can interfere
with the imaging system.
Sounds like there's no end
to the problems you're facing.
I can take care
of the Lissepian.
I need you to get those...
traitors away
from my front door.
They're blocking access
to my place of business
causing a disturbance
on the Promenade
and they're probably
a fire hazard.
They belong in a holding cell!
Every last one of them.
Well, I hate to admit this,
but I agree with you.
From what Chief O'Brien
tells me about strikes
they sound like trouble.
I don't like mobs.
In my opinion, if you need
one to get what you want
it's not worth getting.
Good.
Then you'll haul them away.
I'll do nothing of the sort.
But you said...
I know what I said
but I have strict orders
from Captain Sisko not to...
impinge on your employees'
freedom of expression.
As long as they stay peaceful
and allow your customers access
through the second-level
entrance
I'm not allowed to interfere.
In that case, would you mind
serving some drinks?
Huh!
I didn't think so.
What about the Vulcan?
With their sense of ethics
definitely on the side of labor.
Pass.
I say this one's an "enter."
Lucky guess.
Pass.
He barely set foot in there
when there wasn't a strike.
Mmm. Quark isn't exactly
his favorite person.
Wait a minute.
I can't believe it.
He's an "enter."
Not for long.
Where are you going?
To talk some sense into him.
Commander! Hold on!
I cannot believe
what I'm seeing.
Sir.
If I could explain...
Mr. Worf, do I look like
I'm ready for an explanation?
Three of my senior staff,
brawling on the Promenade.
With all due respect, sir,
we, we weren't brawling.
Maybe you should take
a closer look
at Dr. Bashir's forehead.
Well, he shouldn't
have got in the way.
I was trying... I was trying
to stop the fight.
We were not fighting.
Then what were you doing?
Well, we...
Having a difference
of opinion.
Yeah, I suppose...
towards the end there,
we might have...
done a bit of shoving.
According to Odo
Dr. Bashir was shoved
over a table.
Now, that was an accident.
It was just that things
got a little out of hand.
Things got more than
a little out of hand.
I suppose I'm going to have
to talk to Quark myself.
Find a way
to settle this strike
get things back
to normal around here.
Uh, Captain?
Can we leave now?
I'll tell Constable Odo
to let you go...
in the morning.
Well, I hope you're proud
of yourselves.
Captain, believe me...
I want this strike settled
as much as you do.
Then settle it.
It's not that simple.
Make it simple.
Sit down with your brother
and hammer out
an agreement today.
Captain, I'm afraid
you don't understand
what a delicate
situation this is.
Even talking with strikers
would be a violation
of the most sacred precepts
of Ferengi culture.
Maybe I don't know much
about Ferengi culture
but I do know who holds
the lease on your bar.
The Federation.
And I couldn't ask
for better landlords.
That's because
we don't ask you
to pay your rent
or to reimburse us
for your maintenance repairs
or the drain
on the station's power supply.
You're a very generous people.
Until today.
Let's see.
Five years of back rent
plus power consumption,
plus repairs...
Do you know
how much latinum that is?
A lot.
That's right.
I'll talk to my brother.
I'm glad we're in agreement.
Labor... Labor...
Where's wages?
Wages are here.
Oh, wages...
Come in.
What do you want?
Here.
What's this?
It's the amount of latinum
I'm willing to transfer
into your private account
if you'll just end this strike.
Are we talking about slips,
strips
or bars?
Slips.
All right, strips.
It wouldn't matter
if it were bars.
I'm not going to end the strike
unless you meet our demands.
Rom, we shouldn't be fighting...
we're brothers.
Not when it comes to business.
We're nothing
but employer and employee.
You've said so yourself.
I was wrong.
No.
You weren't.
Rom, can't we talk about this?
There's only one thing
I have to say to you.
"Workers of the world unite.
You have nothing to lose
but your chains."
What's happened to you?
Ah.
It's about time you got back.
Brunt.
That's Liquidator Brunt to you.
I see you remember me.
Who could forget?
What do you want?
Quark, don't worry.
I'm here to help.
The Ferengi Commerce Authority
has ordered me to end
this nasty little
labor dispute of yours.
How do you propose to do that?
By any means necessary.
I hear Quark had only
14 customers all day.
And he'll have
even less tomorrow.
I've been talking with people
all over the station
and support
for our cause is growing.
Quark will have to settle...
either that
or go out of business.
I don't know.
Quark can be awful stubborn.
I think he'd rather lose
the bar than give in to us.
Don't be such a pessimist.
Remember Rule
of Acquisition 263:
"Never allow doubt to tarnish
your lust for latinum."
Your brother can quote
Rules of Acquisition, too.
I believe his favorite is 211:
"Employees are the rungs
on the ladder of success.
Don't hesitate to step on them."
My ex-brother
wasn't quoting
the Rules of Acquisition
when he came
to see me yesterday.
Hmm. What did he say?
He offered me a bribe
if I would end the strike.
Did you take it?
No, I didn't take it!
Don't you see what that means?
He's getting desperate.
A few more days and we'll get
everything we want.
Brunt.
FCA.
It's not my fault!
They made me do it!
It was all his idea!
Forgive me!
If this were Ferenginar...
I'd have you all taken
to the spire
of the Tower of Commerce
displayed to the crowds
in the Great Marketplace below
and then shoved off...
one by one!
Small children would bet
on where you would land
and your spattered remains
would be sold
as feed mulch for gree worms.
Spare me.
I'm old.
I'm fragile.
I'll push the rest of them
off myself.
I thought you said you
weren't afraid of the FCA.
I lied.
Don't let him intimidate you.
We're not on Ferenginar.
Lucky for you.
But the FCA understands
that living
on this station has...
c-corrupted you.
You've been tempted
by unwholesome Bajoran ideals
exposed to the twisted values
of the Federation,
and because of that
we are willing to forgive.
Really?
But don't confuse our mercy
with weakness.
If you are not back at your jobs
tomorrow morning
your financial accounts
on Ferenginar
will be confiscated,
your families will be fined
and your trading permits
revoked.
You'll be ruined...
reduced to utter destitution.
Am I... understood?
Good.
I thought so.
Don't bother getting up.
Would you get up?
Come on.
Let him stay there.
That's where he belongs.
The question is:
Where do we belong?
On our knees... like Frool?
Or standing tall
like Sean O'Brien?
Who's Sean O'Brien?
He was a union man...
a man who gave his life
to earn a decent wage
for his fellow workers.
Brunt wouldn't have
intimidated him
and he won't intimidate me.
What about our accounts
on Ferenginar?
If your accounts on Ferenginar
were worth anything
you wouldn't be working
as a waiter.
I'm telling you...
nothing has changed.
Victory is within our grasp.
All we have to do is take it.
Now, are you with me?
Yes!
I said are you with me?
Then let's get back
on that picket line
and show Quark
what we're made of.
Can I get up now?
Look sharp now.
No slouching.
Remember...
in unity, there is strength.
So be strong.
Chief, may I speak with you?
Sure.
What's on your mind?
I feel I owe you an apology.
I allowed our argument
in Quark's to get out of hand.
I think there was plenty
of blame to spread around.
Nonetheless, we are
Starfleet officers
and Starfleet officers do
not brawl with each other.
It wasn't much of a brawl,
really.
I grabbed you, you shoved me
and Julian was tossed
over a table.
Well, it never
should have happened
and under normal circumstances
it never would have,
but there's something
about this station
I find... unsettling.
You'll get used to it.
Perhaps.
But in the meantime,
I think I've found a solution.
I'm going to move my quarters
to the Defiant.
You're going to live
on the Defiant?
I've already discussed
it with Captain Sisko.
And he said yes?
As long as it doesn't
interfere with my duties.
But... you'll be living
out there all by yourself.
I know.
That was pretty impressive...
standing up to Brunt
the way you did.
Who'd have thought I had such
natural leadership skills?
Oh, I knew it all along.
Really?
No.
I didn't think so.
Well, you surprised
a lot of people
including me.
I've got to get ready.
I'm having dinner with Julian.
He's a lucky man.
And almost as brave as you are.
Psst.
Rom.
She kissed me.
There's no accounting
for taste.
Rom, we have to talk.
Are you ready to give
in to our demands?
Of course not.
Then there's nothing
to talk about.
There's plenty to talk about.
The FCA's involved now.
And those Nausicaans
working for Brunt
aren't just for show.
I'm not going to let
Brunt intimidate me.
Don't you see, Rom?
You should be intimidated.
There's no telling
what Brunt might do
and I don't want you
to get hurt.
You never cared
what happened to me before.
I always cared about you.
I tried to protect you.
Save you from yourself.
How? By telling me I was
an idiot my whole life?
I had to be tough on you.
I was trying to make
you a better Ferengi.
What you were trying to do
was make yourself
feel important.
Making me feel dumb
made you feel smart.
But I'm not dumb
and you're not half as smart
as you think you are.
Rom, you have to listen to me.
The FCA doesn't have
to answer to anyone.
And if Brunt decides
to get rid of you
I won't be able to stop him.
Look at it this way.
If Brunt gets rid of me
then all your problems
are solved.
You always said you wanted
to be an only child.
Doesn't that hurt?
I'm sure it does.
Most Nausicaan games do.
Speaking of pain...
did you talk to your brother?
We talked.
And?
I need more time.
Time, like latinum,
is a highly limited commodity.
Look,
you're here to help me, right?
Wrong.
I'm here to enforce Ferengi law
and to protect Ferengi tradition
and that means putting an end
to this strike.
Now, I can see that we are
going to have to make...
an example of someone.
What kind of example?
Oh, I'm sure that we'll
come up with something
that will get
people's attention.
I, uh... don't want
my brother hurt.
Oh, I wasn't thinking of him.
Attack the leader
of a movement
you risk creating a martyr.
No, Rom must not be touched.
Our target must be someone...
unexpected.
Someone he cares about...
like that dabo girl.
Leeta.
But she's not even Ferengi.
I know.
That's what makes it
so memorable.
But she has such...
delicate lobes.
I'm afraid I couldn't bring
myself to give the order.
No, let's see.
Who else...
does Rom care about?
Boys?
Me?
But I'm on your side.
Ironic...
isn't it?
I thought I wasn't allowed
to have any visitors.
Dr. Bashir made an exception.
He said you were almost killed.
It's nothing to smile about.
Those Nausicaans shattered
my left eye socket
broke two of my ascending ribs
and punctured my lower lung.
If Odo hadn't come along
when he did...
Does it hurt?
Of course, it hurts.
Too bad.
If you're going
to stand there and gloat
you can leave right now.
I'm not done gloating.
Don't you get it?
This was a message for you.
Well, it's not going to work.
I wish Brunt had known that.
Odo has him and the Nausicaans
in a holding cell.
He says
it's an open-and-shut case.
It's an open-and-shut
case all right
but I'm not going
to press charges.
You're not?
Of course not.
I'm in enough trouble
with the FCA as it is.
But then Odo will
have to let them go.
Either way, the FCA
will just send
another Liquidator
and that one will make
an example of you.
Then you'll be the one gloating.
I don't want to gloat.
I want to end the strike.
So, give us what we want.
Rom, I can't!
I'm not going against 10,000
years of Ferengi tradition.
You're just afraid of the FCA.
Of course,
I'm afraid of the FCA.
They crushed my eye socket.
And if you had any sense,
you'd be afraid of them, too.
If this strike
doesn't get settled soon
we're both going
to find ourselves
tossed out
of the nearest airlock.
You have to dissolve the union.
At least officially.
What do you mean?
I mean...
I mean, you
dissolve the union...
make it look like I've won...
and I'll give you
everything you want.
You'll meet our demands?
That's what I just said,
you idiot.
Even sick leave?
Even sick leave.
And six months from now
when the FCA isn't
watching my books so closely
you'll get your raises.
Six months!
It's the best I can do!
No, it's not.
All you have to do is make up
one of your fake
business ledgers for the FCA.
They'll never
know the difference.
Shh!
All right.
You'll get your raises
by the end of the week
but the union dies here...
today...
and that's my final offer.
Better?
Much.
I thought about
getting you a plant
but somehow
it didn't seem right.
A wise decision.
So I brought you this instead.
It's a collection
of my favorite Klingon operas.
Think about it.
You can lie in bed
and pipe them through
the Defiant's com system
and play them
as loud as you like.
A thoughtful gift.
You know, Worf
in the end,
living on the Defiant
isn't going to change anything.
You're still going
to have to get used
to life on the station.
I am not sure I agree.
Sooner or later,
you're going to have to adapt.
Perhaps in the end, it'll be all
of you that have to adapt to me.
Come in! Come in!
Welcome back.
Why don't you try your luck
at the dabo wheel?
Remember, every Bajoran
gets one free spin.
You're in a good mood.
I just got a raise.
Major!
I must say you are looking
particularly cleansed today.
Just get me
two mugs of synthale
a double order
of hasperat, and, uh...
hold the conversation?
No wonder I missed you.
Ah! Rom, there you are.
Why aren't you
in your waiter's uniform?
I'll have
a large snail juice, please
straight up.
You know there's
no drinking on the job.
That's no way to talk
to a customer.
You're not a customer,
you're an employee.
Not anymore.
I've wiped my last table
and mixed my last Black Hole.
Starting today,
I'm one of the station's
diagnostic and repair
technicians, junior grade...
night shift.
You're quitting?
Effective immediately.
I gave you
everything you wanted.
I know, but if the strike
taught me anything
it's that I do a lot better
when you're not around.
Don't worry.
I'll keep
your holosuites running
and fix your replicators
when they're broken.
I think this'll be really
good for our relationship.
I don't.
Think about it from
my point of view.
If I keep working for you,
all I have to look forward to
is waiting for you to die
so I can inherit the bar.
Well, I don't want you to die.
And besides, I deserve
to have a life of my own now.
But without me
looking after you...
I'll do fine.
I suppose you will.
I'll miss you.
No, you won't.
I'll be here all the time,
only I'll be a paying customer.
Now, get me my snail juice...
Brother.
Coming up.