( grunting )
( muted screaming )
( muted, distorted
alarm ringing )
( gasps )
You all right?
What time is it?
0400.
Your hearing starts
in four hours.
I suggest trying
to get some sleep.
You've got a big day
ahead of you.
( dings )
This hearing will come to order.
We are here to consider the
request of the Klingon Empire
that Lieutenant Commander Worf
be extradited for trial
on charges of murder.
Advocate Ch'Pok.
You may present
your charges.
The Klingon Empire makes
the following allegations
against Lieutenant
Commander Worf:
That on stardate 49648
while commanding
the Starship Defiant
he knowingly fired upon
and destroyed a Klingon
civilian transport ship
near the Pentath system.
That as a result
of that action
441 Klingon civilians
were killed.
It is my intention to prove
that Mr. Worf was
grossly negligent
in his command
of the Defiant.
That his lust for combat
overrode his good judgment.
I ask only that he
be returned to us
to face the judgment
of his own people.
Thank you.
The Advocate
neglected to mention
in his opening statement
that at the time in question
the Defiant was under attack
by two Klingon warships.
This was a combat situation
with hundreds of lives at stake.
It was at that moment,
when suddenly
the transport ship de-cloaked
in front of the Defiant.
Worf gave the order to fire.
Not because he was
reckless or negligent
but because he believed
he was firing on a warship.
We intend to show that the
destruction of the transport
was a tragic
but unavoidable accident.
I will hear formal evidence
beginning tomorrow afternoon
at 1500 hours.
I want to know everything
there is to know
about the Klingon
who was commanding
that transport ship.
You suspect it wasn't
just an innocent passenger run.
I'm going to argue
that he saw the battle
and then decided to join it
that he de-cloaked in order
to attack the Defiant.
Not the smartest
decision he ever made.
That's where you come in.
Use your contacts
in the Empire
and find out something
about this Captain I can use.
Was he reckless?
Did he have a reputation
for drinking?
Did he have a death wish?
Something.
I'll see what I can do.
CH'POK:
Captain.
The witnesses
I intend to call.
Thank you.
A remarkable
station, Captain.
Thank you.
We don't get many Klingon
visitors anymore.
After this case is over
you might be seeing
a lot more of us.
Oh?
When Worf is extradited
the Federation will
be forced to admit
that one of its officers
committed a massacre.
That will put you
on the defensive
throughout the Quadrant.
And while you're busy
trying to repair
a badly damaged reputation
we'll find ourselves
with certain...
opportunities.
An opportunity to annex
more Cardassian space
and set up additional
military bases in this sector?
Possibly.
But in any case, Worf
is about to present us
with something we never
could have won in battle.
Sympathy.
Any move we make
against you
will be seen as
a legitimate response
to an outrageous slaughter.
You're presuming
an awful lot.
Worf maintains
his innocence.
And you're about
to remind me
that the burden
of proof is mine.
It's an interesting system
of justice you have, Captain.
It does have
its flaws, however.
It emphasizes procedure
over substance
form over fact.
I'm sorry if you feel it
puts you at a disadvantage.
On the contrary.
I look forward to
fighting on your terms.
This is not a fight.
It's the search
for the truth.
The truth must be won.
I'll see you
on the battlefield.
I have studied
Commander Worf's reports
the Defiant's sensor logs
and the reports of the
other officers on the Bridge.
And I believe
every word of it.
It's a matter of pride
for the Federation
that Starfleet officers
never lie or commit fraud.
So I will accept
the facts of the case
as they have
been submitted.
Admiral, if there are
no facts in dispute,
then this hearing would
appear to be at an end.
We Klingons
are not concerned
with matters of fact
and circumstance.
What matters to us
is what was in Worf's heart
when he gave
the order to fire.
Was he just a Starfleet officer
doing his duty,
or was he a Klingon warrior
reveling in the battle?
That is why I am here.
Because if he was a Klingon
lost in the bloodlust
of combat,
only we can judge him,
not you.
We can't put a man's
heart on trial.
It's a subjective issue
that cannot be reasoned
in a court of law.
I ask that the Advocate
be limited
to arguing the evidence
in this case.
Someone told me this was
a search for the truth.
Should we not
follow that search
wherever it takes us?
The question of Commander Worf's
motive is relevant.
I will allow you
to explore this issue
but only as far
as logic permits.
I bow to your judgment.
You may call
your first witness.
CH'POK:
You are considered
something of an expert
on Klingon society,
aren't you, Commander?
My previous host, Curzon, would
have called himself an expert.
I tend to think of myself
as having a passing familiarity
with your culture.
In your opinion,
as someone with a...
passing familiarity
with our culture
wouldn't you say
the Klingons are
a violent, warrior race?
Yes, there is that
aspect to your people.
Would you agree that
one of the things
that makes a Klingon
warrior so formidable
is his predatory instinct,
his blood lust, if you will?
I'd agree with that.
Now, when Worf
was on the Defiant
engaged in combat,
don't you think
his predatory instinct
took over?
I think that instinct
was present
but I've seen Mr. Worf
restrain it before.
How do you know so much
about how he behaves in battle?
In the holosuite,
we've fought many times.
You mean you practiced
with Mr. Worf.
You played with him.
Oh, no.
When we fight, we fight.
I've made it very clear
to Mr. Worf
that I never want him
to take it easy on me
because I'm a woman or a Trill.
Have you ever been injured?
A few bruises here and there.
A broken finger once.
Nothing serious,
and I've given him
a few lumps
of his own.
CH'POK:
So you're not afraid
of Mr. Worf.
I'm no fool.
I can see the killer instinct
in his eyes.
And I know he could
kill me if he wants to.
But that look always goes away.
He knows when to stop.
Jadt.
Admiral, at this time
I would like to enter into
evidence files I obtained
from the defendant's private
data base this morning.
SISKO:
Objection.
There's been no search order
issued for those files.
This is a violation
of Mr. Worf's privacy.
The Captain is correct.
Without a properly
executed search order
or the permission of the
defendant, any information
you have accessed
from his private data base
may not be admitted
into evidence.
Ah. I see.
Well, I obviously
have no search order
so I'll ask you, Worf.
May I enter this file
into evidence
or do you have
something to hide?
( whispers ):
Don't play his game.
I have nothing to hide.
Use whatever you wish.
CH'POK:
Commander Dax,
are you familiar
with the holosuite program known
as "The Battle of Tong Vey"?
Yes.
It's one of the programs
Mr. Worf brought with him
from the Enterprise.
Describe it for us.
It's an historical reenactment
of one
of the epic Klingon battles.
10,000 warriors under the
command of Emperor Sompek
conquer the city of Tong Vey
after a long siege.
A glorious battle.
When Worf recreates it
in the holosuite
what role does he play?
Sompek.
Of course.
The conqueror's role.
One of our
greatest heroes.
Tell me, Commander.
What was the final order
Sompek gave to his men
once they had conquered
the city of Tong Vey?
Commander?
He told them to burn
the city to the ground
and kill everyone in it.
Everyone?
Not just the soldiers,
but the people of the town, too?
Civilians?
Women?
Children?
Yes.
CH'POK:
Now, Commander
when Mr. Worf runs this program,
does he give the final order
to destroy the city
and kill all of the inhabitants?
It's not the same thing.
It's a simulation...
Answer the question.
That's the way the program
is supposed to end.
You have to give that command...
Admiral
I ask that the witness
be instructed
to answer the question
"yes" or "no."
Yes or no, Commander.
Yes.
CH'POK:
Of course he does.
Because he is
a Klingon warrior.
He doesn't have
the same moral code
as a Starfleet officer.
He is one of us--
a killer, a predator
among sheep.
Objection!
Restrain yourself, Advocate.
I have only one more
question for this witness
Admiral.
Commander Dax
when was the last time
Worf used that program?
( padd beeping )
The day before he left
on the convoy mission.
The day before.
I have nothing further.
Captain, you ordered Worf
to command the Defiant
on the mission in
question, did you not?
That's right.
How did you describe
the mission to Worf?
An outbreak
of Rudellian plague
has struck the Cardassian colony
on Pentath III.
The Cardassians are
preparing several convoys
of medical supplies
and relief workers
but the Pentath system
borders Klingon territory
and the Cardassians
are worried about raids.
Well, Pentath is a strategically
important system.
The Klingons will
try to stop them.
The problem is the Cardassians
don't have enough warships
available to protect
the relief convoy.
They've asked
for Starfleet protection
and because of the humanitarian
nature of the request
we've agreed.
There will be seven convoys
headed for Pentath III
in the next week.
Each of them protected
by a Federation starship.
The Defiant has been assigned
to escort convoy six
and I've chosen you
to be in command.
CH'POK:
Why did you select Worf
for this mission?
I felt that he was
an experienced officer
who was ready to take on
greater responsibilities.
He had a distinguished record
and obviously understood
the Klingons.
Weren't you a little worried,
Captain, that Worf--
a famed Klingon warrior--
might jump at the chance
for combat
and forget about
the plague victims?
If I were, I wouldn't
have given him the assignment.
And you're sure you
made your instructions
perfectly clear--
that Commander Worf
knew he was on a
humanitarian relief mission
that he was not being
sent out to seek combat?
Yes.
Thank you, Captain.
I have nothing
further for you.
Captain, since you are
also acting as defense counsel
if you wish to add anything
to the record
you're free to do so.
Not at this time, Admiral.
Call your next witness.
It was about 1700 hours.
I was doing some cleanup work.
Dr. Bashir was at the
bar talking to Etheria
one of the dabo girls.
Have you ever seen
the wormhole open?
No, wait.
It wasn't Etheria;
it was Glidia.
Have you ever seen
the wormhole open?
Or was it... Midia?
CH'POK:
Mr. Quark, is this necess...?
No, no. No, it was Ralidia,
and she was with Morn
and he was the one
who turned to her and said...
Can we get back
to the matter at hand, please?
Oh, right.
Um... well, as I said
I was cleaning up,
and I saw Mr. Worf come in.
CH'POK:
Was there anything unusual
about that?
No. He comes in here
all the time.
But he was in a good mood.
And that's unusual?
Well, he's a Klingon
and you people are rarely
in what I would call good moods.
Not that you're anything
but a pleasant, charming race.
Let's get back to Mr. Worf.
Describe what happened next.
He came in, he ordered a drink--
prune juice, I believe--
and we started to talk.
I'd heard
about the convoy mission
so I asked him about it
and he said he was going
to be commanding the Defiant.
What was his attitude?
Hard to say.
He's a very private man.
He doesn't share a lot
with his bartender.
Did he seem...
afraid of the mission?
No.
Did he seem excited
by the mission?
Not excited exactly.
Then what exactly?
I just remember asking him...
What happens if the Klingons
go after the convoy?
And then he got this
funny look on his face.
He put down
his prune juice
looked me right in the
eye, and then he said...
I hope they do.
"I hope they do."
Well, it would appear
Commander Worf's
hopes were answered.
I have nothing further.
What do you have
for me, Constable?
Background on
the Klingon transport captain.
He'd never been
in the military
and he was known
to his family and friends
as a quiet, efficient man
who was content in his position.
Doesn't sound like a man
who'd suddenly decide
to take on the Defiant.
No.
What about this story of theirs
that the transport ship
just wandered off course
into a combat area?
I checked the flight plan
the Captain filed
and the projected course
was near the border.
It would have taken only a
very slight error in navigation
for the ship to stray
into the fight.
But why did he drop his cloak
right in front of the Defiant?
Ah, that's the question
no one seems able to answer.
No one seems able,
or no one seems willing?
Oh, they're too willing
to answer questions--
that's the problem.
I'm always suspicious of people
who are eager to help
a police officer.
Start looking into
the passengers on that ship.
Maybe someone with a grudge
against Worf
or the Federation was aboard--
someone who could have
seized control
of the ship and taken
it into the battle.
I'm reaching, I know.
But at the moment,
it's all we have.
I'll keep looking.
There were two Klingon ships--
a bird-of-prey
and an old battle cruiser.
One would engage us while
the other went after the convoy.
Then they'd switch.
The first ship going
after the Cardassians
while the second ship
came after us.
We've lost the number
three starboard shield.
Come about.
The cruiser has taken us
too far away from the convoy.
Try to keep our port side
to the Klingons.
Aye, sir.
This went on for-- I don't know,
maybe five minutes.
They'd come at us, try to draw
us away from the Cardassians.
We'd head back.
Then the bird-of-prey came
toward us off the port bow.
I have phaser lock.
Fire.
We damaged them but not much.
We'd seen them do this cloak-
and-run maneuver a few times
and Commander Worf
thought he saw a pattern.
We have them now.
Come to course 185 mark 278.
Stand by quantum
torpedoes, full spread.
Aye, sir.
I ran a quick sensor sweep
then I reported.
I'm picking up a tachyon surge
directly ahead.
Fire.
SISKO:
When did you realize
it wasn't a bird-of-prey?
As soon as it exploded.
Oh, my God.
We were all stunned.
I scanned for survivors,
but there were none.
Chief, do you believe
Worf was correct in
giving the order to fire?
I stand by his decision.
Is there any question
in your mind about his motives?
No, sir.
I've known Commander Worf
for nine years.
He's an honorable man.
He would never intentionally
fire on an unarmed ship.
Thank you, Chief.
I'm curious, Chief.
You say you stand by
Commander Worf's decision.
Do you agree with it?
I completely support him.
That's not my question.
Do you agree
with his decision?
I wasn't in command.
It's not my place
to question his judgment.
What if you were in command?
What would you have done?
I don't know.
Chief, how many years have
you been in Starfleet?
Twenty-two.
And how many combat
situations have you been in?
I couldn't even guess.
Try.
100, 150.
For the record
Chief O'Brien has been
in 235 separate engagements
and Starfleet has
decorated him 15 times.
I would like to have him
declared an expert
in the area
of starship combat.
Any objection?
None.
Chief O'Brien,
if Mr. Worf had been injured
could you have taken over
command of that ship?
I would have.
Let's say that happened.
You're in command.
You're chasing
the bird-of-prey.
It cloaks.
You anticipate
your opponent's maneuver
so you give the order.
Come about
to 185 mark 278.
Stand by quantum
torpedoes, full spread.
CH'POK:
The crew obeys.
The ship comes about.
And then your helm officer
tells you...
I'm picking up a tachyon surge,
directly ahead.
Now, stop right there.
Freeze that moment in time.
Everything rides
on your next decision.
Do you give the order to fire?
This isn't a fair question.
It didn't really
happen this way.
I wasn't in command.
CH'POK:
I'm not interested
in whether you think
it's a fair question or not.
You're in command.
There's a ship out there
de-cloaking.
You don't know what it is.
Do you fire?
No.
But that's just my opinion now,
after the fact.
I wasn't in command that day.
Things look a lot different when
you're sitting in that chair.
I'm sure they do.
Captain Sisko
mind if I sit down?
I understand you're
going to put Worf
on the stand
this afternoon.
That's right.
May I make a suggestion?
Concede.
Let me take him back
to the Empire
and I'll make sure
he's not put to death.
In fact, I'll
defend him myself.
You?
What matters to me
is the thrill of the fight,
not which side I'm on.
And I think we both know
the extradition fight is over.
You're not making
this offer out of kindness.
You want the Federation
to concede
so the convoys will stop
and the Klingons can move in
on the Pentath system.
As humans would say,
that would be icing on the cake.
I wouldn't try eating that cake
just yet, if I were you.
But you have told me one thing
I needed to know--
you're worried about what Worf
might say on the stand.
I'm not worried--
but you should be.
ODO:
Captain.
Good news or bad?
Bad. I checked
the backgrounds
of every passenger
on that transport.
None had any
connection with Worf
or grudge against
the Federation
or any motive
for seizing control
of the ship and
attacking the Defiant.
But I'm still not
giving up.
I appreciate that
but I get the feeling
that at this point
the only one who can
help Worf is Worf.
The escort mission had
proceeded smoothly for two days.
We detected
several subspace distortions
which might have been
cloaked ships
but nothing definite.
SISKO:
So, what was the first sign
of trouble, Mr. Worf?
( alarm blaring )
There was no warning.
A bird-of-prey just de-cloaked
off the port quarter.
Raise shields.
Arm phasers.
Commander, another
ship's de-cloaking.
It's an older battle cruiser.
She's going after the convoy.
Bring us about.
SISKO:
How did you feel
when the Klingons attacked?
Were you excited?
Of course.
I am a Klingon.
We live for battle.
So that's all
that mattered to you--
the chance to fight?
No, sir. Whatever my
personal feelings may be
I do not allow them
to interfere with my duty
or my professional
judgment.
Chief O'Brien says
that he disagrees
with your decision to fire.
How do you respond to that?
I respect the Chief's opinion.
He and I have served together
for many years
and I consider him a friend.
However, he was not
in command that day.
What difference does that make?
It makes all
the difference.
He is looking back
at a decision
analyzing it weeks later.
As the Commanding Officer
of the Defiant
it was my duty to look forward
to anticipate
every possible situation.
Did you anticipate
encountering a civilian ship
on this mission?
I knew our convoy
would be passing
through civilian
shipping lanes, but...
in my judgment, the chances
of a civilian vessel
de-cloaking in the middle
of a battle were remote.
I decided that if I were
engaged in combat
I would not hesitate to
fire at a de-cloaking ship.
Mr. Worf, I want you to think
about the civilians who died
on that transport ship
and answer one question.
Under the same set
of circumstances
would you do it again?
Yes, sir.
If I had hesitated,
I would have been negligent.
I would have been risking
my ship, my crew
and the entire convoy.
Thank you.
Worf...
why are you considered
an outcast among Klingons?
I sided with the Federation
during the invasion
of Cardassia.
For that, Chancellor Gowron
stripped me of my name
and my family honor.
So you acted out of conscience
and you were punished for it.
How do you feel about that?
Angry? Bitter?
I am angry about
the treatment I have received.
I felt it was unjust.
Of course you are.
Who wouldn't be?
What happened affected
your entire family.
The House of Mogh
was brought down.
Your brother was ejected
from the High Council
in disgrace
your lands seized
and now your son, Alexander,
has to bear the stigma
of being the son
of a traitor.
Did I miss anything?
No.
In your opinion
what do they think of you
in the Empire, Worf?
I am hated.
Why? Because
of what you did?
Yes.
Are you sure it's not
something more basic?
What is that supposed to mean?
Isn't it obvious?
You were raised by humans
on Earth
and now you wear their uniform.
Haven't you really always been
a traitor in your heart?
No.
Are you telling us
that you live with humans,
but your heart is Klingon?
Yes.
But if your heart
is Klingon,
how could you fire
upon your own people?
They fired the first shot.
And when that happened,
they became my enemies.
Then why aren't you glad you
destroyed that transport?
It was filled with your
enemies and their children.
There is nothing honorable
about killing those
who cannot defend themselves.
Are you telling me
that you would never
attack a defenseless
opponent?
No. I would not.
Maybe I was wrong about you.
Maybe you aren't really
Klingon in your heart.
A true Klingon rejoices
at the death
of his enemies--
old, young, armed, unarmed.
All that matters
is the victory.
Tell me, Worf--
did you weep for those children?
I grieve for them.
Grieve for them?
A Klingon does not grieve.
They died in glorious battle.
They are with the honored dead
in Sto-Vo-Kor.
They do not want your grief.
You dishonor their memoryies!
Objection!
Advocate.
WORF:
You will say anything.
You have no honor.
I say this--
you live with humans
because you're afraid
to live with Klingons.
I fear nothing
and if you would like
to pick up a bat'leth
and face me with weapons
instead of words
I will prove it to you.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you, Worf?
You'd love to prove
that you are as strong
and courageous as
any Klingon warrior.
I am a Klingon warrior.
Advocate, you are stepping
well beyond the
bounds of protocol.
And that is why
you told the Ferengi
you hope the Klingons
do come for you.
You wanted to prove
yourself in the eyes
of the only people
that matter to you--
other Klingons!
This will stop, or I will hold
both of you in contempt.
I apologize, Worf.
Actually...
I pity you.
But the person I pity most
is Alexander--
because one day
he will come
to you and ask
"Father, who am I?"
And you will have to tell him
that he is the son
of a small, frightened man
who destroyed
a ship full of children
just to prove
his own courage.
Worf, no!
I thought you told me you'd
never attack an unarmed man.
Perhaps you should
have said
"not unless I get angry."
"Not unless I have
something to prove."
I rest my case.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 49665.3.
The hearing is in recess
and Admiral T'Lara
has retired to her quarters
to begin deliberations.
I wish I could be more
optimistic about her decision.
( door opens )
Constable.
Good news.
Don't worry. If he objects,
I know what to do.
( dings )
Captain Sisko.
Admiral, I apologize
for interrupting
your deliberations
but I have
some new evidence
I'd like to present.
Very well.
I'd like Advocate Ch'Pok
to evaluate the evidence
as an expert witness
on the Klingon Empire.
I will not compel you
to testify, Advocate.
Care to step
onto my battlefield?
Advocate, how would you describe
the current relationship
between the Federation
and the Klingon Empire?
There is no formal relationship
between our two governments.
What would you call us?
Informal friends?
Informal enemies?
I would say
there is potential
for either label.
But at the moment,
neither is entirely accurate.
Hmm, interesting.
Would you agree that,
at the moment
it is difficult for us
to trust each other?
Difficult, but not impossible.
There are things that transcend
our differences.
For example, we trust
that this case
can be decided fairly.
We have faith
in Admiral T'Lara's judgment.
Oh, I'm glad to hear you have
such a profound respect
for the Admiral.
But would it be fair to say
that outside this hearing
you do not entirely trust us?
Well, it is only prudent
that we question your motives
now that we are
no longer allies.
Of course, and
it is only
prudent of us
to question your motives.
After all, aren't there times
when you feel it's in your
best interest to deceive us?
I object to the question.
It is vague
and hypothetical.
Well, can you imagine
any circumstance
in which the Empire
would deceive the Federation?
I have a poor imagination.
Let's see what we
can do to spark it.
Do you recognize these names?
These are the people who were
killed on board the transport.
You're positive?
There are 441 of them.
The names and faces
of these people
are seared into my heart.
This is a list of heroes
who died at the hands
of a coward.
It is a list I can never forget.
They are an interesting group
of people, aren't they?
From every walk
of life--
merchants, soldiers,
artists, shopkeepers...
Children.
We've done
some checking
in their backgrounds
and in our opinion
they all appear to be
a random group of people
who shared only one thing
in common:
They all traveled
on the same ship.
Is that your conclusion as well?
Yes.
And it was just fate
that led these particular people
to board a doomed ship?
Fate is a human concept.
They simply boarded the wrong
ship at the wrong time.
And then... they did it again.
I don't, uh...
think I understand
your line of...
Three months ago
a Klingon transport ship
crashed
in the mountains
of Galorda Prime.
Of course, everyone
assumed the worst--
that the passengers and the crew
had all been killed.
But then, miraculously...
everyone survived.
Do you know anyone
who was on that ship?
No.
Are you sure?
You have the names
of the survivors right there.
I can understand your confusion.
The names in front of you
are identical
to the names on this list.
The people who were killed
in the Defiant incident.
So what does this mean?
441 people somehow survived
a crash on Galorda Prime.
And then a few weeks later
they all decide to take
another trip on the same day
on the same transport ship,
under the same Captain and crew.
And then that ship
is destroyed, too.
This is a very unlucky
group of people,
wouldn't you say?
I am not an expert on luck.
No. You are an expert
on the Klingon Empire.
So, tell me, Advocate
isn't it possible
that there were no civilians
on the transport Worf destroyed?
Isn't it possible
that the ship he saw
was sending out
false sensor images
and that this
whole affair was staged
so that the only Klingon
officer in Starfleet
would be accused
of a massacre
and the Federation
would be forced
to stop escorting
the convoys?
Tell me, Advocate...
isn't it possible?
Yes.
Captain.
I thought you should know
O'Brien and Bashir are throwing
a party for you at Quark's.
Looks like quite a bash.
I am aware of it.
But I have
much on my mind.
Ch'Pok was right.
I did have
something to prove
when I took command
of the convoy.
And I did not realize it
until I stood there,
looking down at him
blood trickling
from his mouth.
In that moment,
I remember thinking
finally, he had given me
what I really wanted--
a reason to attack him.
And I had that
same feeling
when the Klingon ships
first attacked.
Finally, a chance for vengeance.
I should not have
accepted the mission.
I am glad you realize that.
That was your first mistake.
What was your second?
When the ship de-cloaked
I should have checked
the target before I fired.
You're damned right
you should have checked.
You knew there were
civilian ships in the area.
You fired at something
you hadn't identified.
You made a military decision
to protect your ship and crew.
But you're
a Starfleet officer, Worf.
We don't put civilians at risk,
or even potentially at risk
to save ourselves.
Sometimes that means
we lose the battle
and sometimes our lives.
But if you can't make
that choice
then you can't wear
that uniform.
Yes, sir.
At ease, Commander.
Now, all that being true
the reality is
no harm's been done.
There are no dead children
on your conscience.
You got lucky.
I do not feel lucky.
And that's why, despite
everything that's happened
you're going to make
a hell of a Captain someday.
Now, let's go.
They'll all be waiting.
( sighs )
Look, this party
isn't for you
as much as
it is for them.
Things got a little tense
there for a while.
They need a release,
a chance to celebrate.
But I do not feel
like celebrating.
Part of being
a Captain
is knowing when to smile.
Make the troops happy--
even when it's
the last thing in the world
you want to do.
Because they're your troops
and you have
to take care of them.
Life is a great deal more
complicated in this red uniform.
Wait till you get
four pips on that collar.
You'll wish you had gone
into botany.