Here they are.
Welcome.
Recording.
Character sketches
for possible stories.
A Bolian tries to impress
a dabo girl
by wearing a toupee.
A thief disguises
himself as a monk
so he can swindle a Ferengi.
A woman...
traveling alone.
She's come a long way.
Lwaxana?
Oh, hello, Odo.
You've been crying.
I can't help it.
Why?
Because...
I'm pregnant.
It's a miracle.
I never thought
I could have another baby.
Then those were tears
of happiness.
I won't let him do it, Odo.
Who? What?
My husband Jeyal.
He wants to take my baby.
That's why I ran away.
Please, Lwaxana,
try to be calm.
Now, tell me.
Why would your husband
want to take your baby from you?
He's Tavnian.
And?
They believe
in strict separation
of the sexes.
Boys are raised by men,
girls by women.
Why, those poor children
aren't even told
the other sex exists
until they're 16.
And your child is male.
Uh-huh, and the day
Jeyal found out, he said
that he was going
to take my baby away from me
as soon as he was born.
Well, I told him that
that isn't what we agreed...
that he had said that it was
going to be different with us
because I wasn't Tavnian.
But he changed his mind.
During our wedding ceremony
he spoke so beautifully
about why he wanted to marry me
but afterwards...
it was as if I had become
a piece of property in his eyes.
So you ran away.
And it wasn't easy, believe me.
Toward the end, I was
practically a prisoner
in my own house.
Well, now that you've
shown your husband
how determined you are
to be part of your boy's life
perhaps he'll reconsider
his position.
Oh, no, not Jeyal.
He's the most willful man
I've ever met.
Oh! I'm so tired.
I've never needed a friend
more than I do right now.
I... appreciate your situation
and I would like to help...
I knew you would.
You're such a dear, sweet man.
Unfortunately,
I'm also a very busy man.
Oh, believe me, Odo,
the last thing I want
is to become a burden to you.
I know how you value
your privacy.
All I want is a quiet place
where I can have my baby
in peace.
I was about to suggest
the very thing.
I'll find out when the next
transport leaves for Betazed.
Oh, I couldn't
possibly go there.
That's the first place
Jeyal will look for me.
I know him.
He won't give up,
not until he finds me
and gets his son back.
That's why I came to you,
because I knew you'd protect me.
You will protect me,
won't you, Odo?
You're a writer.
I could see
you were somewhere else...
someplace you were inventing.
I'm, uh, working on a story.
I can spot a creative soul
a galaxy away.
My name is Onaya.
Jake Sisko.
Do you live here?
Yes.
I love
Cardassian architecture...
the way things flow together.
Kell used to say
that every element
had to be of a piece
yet have a beauty all its own.
Tavor Kell, the architect?
I knew him when he was in exile.
What was he like?
Shy.
Unsure of himself
and his talent.
Most people would never notice
someone like him
but I have a weakness
for artists.
You wouldn't think
he was shy from his designs.
When I first met him,
they were as timid as he was.
I was always telling him
to stop censoring himself.
He must have listened to you.
I've found artists
have a weakness for me as well.
At least, I hope they do.
I, uh... I've always wondered
what Kell would have designed
if he had lived longer.
He accomplished more
in the years that he had
than most people could
in a dozen lifetimes.
His name is known
throughout the Quadrant.
His buildings will stand
for centuries to come.
Isn't that
what an artist wants...
to be remembered?
Isn't that why you write?
I don't know.
I think it's mostly because
I like to tell stories.
There's no reason
to hide your ambition, Jake.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
I think it's what makes artists
so compelling.
All right.
I-I guess I do want
to be remembered.
So, what are you doing
to make sure you will be?
Well, I'm thinking of going to
the Pennington School on Earth.
You already have the talent
inside you.
I can see it.
You just need someone
to help you bring it
to the surface.
How?
There are ways.
Exercises.
Techniques.
Can you show them to me?
Come to my quarters tonight.
I'll be there.
Are you packed?
Kasidy's ship is going
to be here any minute.
Dad, I-I was thinking
about staying home.
Staying home?
This trip was your idea.
I know.
You mean, you really
want to pass up
three days
in the Bajoran outback?
I thought maybe you and Kasidy
would have a better time
without me.
Oh, lay off
the matchmaking, Jake.
Kasidy and I are doing fine.
It's not just that.
I'm also working on this story
and I don't want to lose
my concentration.
You can write on the trip.
Look, I'm not trying
to talk you into anything.
I don't get leave often,
and I was looking forward
to the three of us
spending time together.
Me, too, but...
I really need to focus on this.
All right.
Good luck with it.
See you in a couple of days.
My marriage was a sham.
What I'd mistaken for love...
was nothing more than a prison.
So... tell me.
Where are you girls headed?
Oh.
A holosuite.
King Arthur's court.
Camelot.
Love betrayed...
Dreams...
shattered.
Look at them.
You'd think somebody died.
I don't know if it's because
she's Betazoid or what
but her mood is contagious.
As soon as she walked in here,
things started getting quiet.
Well, what do you
want me to do about it?
Either cheer her up
or get her to leave
because if you don't,
I'm going to throw her out.
Odo.
Won't you join the party?
Actually, I have some free time
and I was wondering
if you wanted to take a walk.
I would.
I meant Lwaxana.
I would love to.
Sorry.
Maybe next time.
I'm so depressed.
Kestra was six years old
when she died.
My sweet little girl.
I lost my parents,
a sister, a husband.
But nothing...
nothing compared to losing her.
Uh...
I didn't mean
to carry on like that.
I'm sorry.
No, don't apologize.
I think I finally understand
why you're so determined
not to let your husband
take the baby from you.
These are your quarters,
aren't they?
Yes.
Right next to yours.
My replicator is acting up.
Would you mind terribly if,
if we popped in
so I could get a cup
of Gavaline tea?
Of course not.
Uh, the replicator
is right over here.
I'll let Chief O'Brien
know about yours.
Oh, I already did.
He said he'd get to it
as soon as he could.
Gavaline tea.
Is, um... is this
for shape-shifting?
Yes.
Actually, most people
think it's a sculpture.
Well, what do most people know?
Thank you.
May I ask you something, Odo?
Are you over her?
Don't worry.
I'm not going to throw myself
at you if you say yes.
Major Kira
and First Minister Shakaar
are involved now.
How sad.
Not at all.
I'm happy for her.
Well, just don't
go do what I did...
look for someone
to fix your broken heart
then end up pregnant
and on the run.
Ah...
I don't think there's
much danger of that happening.
What is it?
The baby kicked.
May I sit down for a minute?
I, I... I don't
have any furniture.
The floor will do.
Oh.
Uh, how are you feeling now?
Like a changeling
who's had to hold
his shape too long.
Ah.
Well, I, uh...
I think I know how that feels.
Oh...
he's moving.
Here. You want to feel?
There.
Yes.
Oh.
Oh, I'm so tired, Odo.
I don't think I've had
a decent night's sleep
in weeks.
Sometimes, with Betazoid babies
you can actually
sense their thoughts.
Oh, such contentment.
Yes...
I can feel it, too.
You know, someone once said
"Life is a search to find
the peace you once had
when you were safe
inside your mother."
I didn't have a mother.
Oh...
don't worry, it's all right.
You'll find your peace...
just the same.
Lwaxana?
Hmm?
Your replicator isn't
really broken, is it?
No.
I'm sorry
if I made you feel unwelcome.
It's...
it's just my way...
Lwaxana?
Yes?
It's Jake... Jake Sisko.
Remember me?
Come in.
I, uh...
I brought some of my stories
for you to read.
I don't need to.
Oh.
I thought maybe...
It's what you're going
to be writing next
that interests me.
You seem nervous, Jake.
Maybe a little.
That's understandable.
You should be nervous
when you start something new.
Although maybe
not this nervous.
Haven't you ever been alone
in a woman's quarters before?
Whatever you're thinking,
put it out of your mind.
You're here to work.
Now...
what's the most ambitious story
you ever wanted to tell?
I have an idea for a novel.
It's sort of autobiographical.
The main character's mother
dies.
It's not about that, really.
It's about a lot of things.
So many, it all seems
so big to you right now.
You're afraid
that you can't do it justice.
Yeah.
But I'll bet you know
what the first line is.
How'd you know that?
I have something
I want to show you.
Revalus used it
when he wrote The Wait.
You knew him?
I have a weakness for artists.
I told you that.
I want you to have it.
I don't know what to say.
Thank you.
There's more.
Here...
Paper?
I've never worked
on paper before.
Revalus used to say
that "a writer should
put pen to paper
as if he were a painter
putting brush to canvas."
It's a part of what
he called "visceral writing."
What's that?
It's one of the techniques
I told you about.
Can you teach it to me?
That's why you're here.
Isn't it?
The opening line
of your novel...
write it down.
Now, keep going.
What do you mean, "keep going"?
Write whatever comes to you.
The idea is to create
a stream of consciousness
and see where that takes you.
You can edit later.
Just write the first thing
that comes to mind.
I won't look.
Let the words tumble out of you.
Don't censor them.
Feel the pen...
in your hand...
the texture of the paper.
Let yourself fall into a rhythm.
You feel where my thumbs are?
Mm-hmm.
That's your foramen magnum.
It's a focal point
for the body's
bioelectric field.
There's another one...
here.
The Vulcans call them qui'lari.
The Indians of ancient Earth
called them shakras.
I know how to stimulate them
to make you feel restful...
or energized...
or even...
creative.
This isn't bad.
I told you I could help you.
Let the words...
flow, Jake.
Let them flow.
Yes...
that's it.
Let them flow.
There you are.
Got you that time.
That's not fair.
I didn't know
you could do surfaces.
Well, now you do.
Shall we try again?
Are you sure you're up to it?
Oh, absolutely.
I haven't had so much fun
in months.
Really?
Neither have I.
Security to Odo.
Go ahead.
A transport just arrived
from the Umani sector.
The man you asked us
to look out for was on it.
Acknowledged.
You know what to do.
Aye, sir.
It's my husband, isn't it?
Stay here.
I'll handle this.
You'd better have a good reason
for dragging me in like this.
I'm Chief of Station Security.
That's all the reason I need.
Well, well.
You're the changeling.
Odo... if I remember correctly.
And what of it?
Lwaxana told me all about you.
How you broke her heart.
Strange she'd come running
to you for protection.
Her pregnancy must have her
confused, poor woman.
I find her remarkably
clear-headed.
She doesn't want to see you
so you might as well
turn around and go home.
I've come a long way.
I'm not leaving here
empty-handed.
She is not going back with you.
I am not talking about her.
I'm talking about my son.
I intend to see
that he is raised by men...
not by the pampering foolishness
of women.
I hate to disappoint you
but Lwaxana has no intention
of giving him up to you.
Her intentions
do not concern me.
As her husband,
I have a legal right to my son.
I've been familiarizing myself
with Tavnian laws.
It's well established
that the male child
is considered the property
of the mother's husband.
Exactly.
Not the child's father.
The mother's husband.
By the time Lwaxana gives birth
you won't be her husband.
We're getting married?
If you take me as your husband
in a legal Tavnian ceremony
your marriage to Jeyal
will automatically be annulled
and he'll lose his claim
to the baby.
I-I... I don't quite
know what to say.
I'm... well, I'm just touched
by your willingness
to do this for me.
Well, it's not so much, really.
We'll remain husband and wife
for a few months
long enough to satisfy
Tavnian law
and then get an annulment
of our own.
It's not as if I was planning
to marry someone else.
Even so... thank you.
There is one thing
I don't understand.
Jeyal insisted on staying
to witness the ceremony.
He did?
Is that a problem?
In a, uh, Tavnian wedding
the groom must stand
before the bride
and tell her why he wants
to marry her.
And then, in front
of his family and friends
he must proclaim
his love for her
and convince her
to accept him as her husband.
Well, I trust I can count on you
to accept me
even if I just stand there
and read last week's
criminal activity report.
Um... no, no, no, you don't
quite understand.
If anyone present
doubts the groom's sincerity
they can challenge the validity
of the marriage.
You mean... I have to convince
Jeyal that I want to marry you?
I've never been able
to write like this.
Ideas are coming so fast.
I can barely keep up with them.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Jake...
It's okay.
It's just a nosebleed.
You should rest.
I'll be all right.
It's already stopped.
Where was I?
Did I miss something?
I didn't know Odo was getting
married till this morning.
I'm not sure he knew either.
Who's he?
I think that's
Lwaxana's husband.
Good of him to come.
Well...
I'm so glad you could make it.
I'm sure you are.
It's not too late
to call this off.
Your dignity's important to you.
I understand that.
I would not want
anyone to see me
go through a charade like this.
If you don't mind
this is a very special
moment for me.
In keeping
with Tavnian tradition
I stand before you
here in my home
among my worldly possessions
and declare my wish
to add this woman
to that which is mine.
She is as kind
as she is beautiful
and I want her to be
part of my life
from this day on.
Marry me, Lwaxana.
Am I the only one
who finds this a pale
declaration of love?
You could be talking
about any woman!
Lwaxana is not just any woman!
Not to me.
Then prove it to us.
Before I met her...
my world was...
a much smaller place.
I kept to myself.
I didn't need anyone else
and I took pride in that.
The truth is...
I was ashamed of what I was.
Afraid that if people saw
how truly different I was
they would recoil from me.
Lwaxana saw
how different I was...
and she didn't recoil.
She wanted to see more.
For the first time in my life...
someone wanted me as I was.
And that changed me...
forever.
The day I met her
is the day I stopped
being alone.
And I want her
to be part of my life
from this day on.
Marry me, Lwaxana.
Let me into your light.
Lwaxana?
I give myself to you...
forever and always.
I say for all to hear
that this woman is mine.
If anyone challenges
my claim to her
let them do so now.
I present to you...
my beloved wife.
- Odo.
- Chief.
- Congratulations.
Congratulations.
Well done.
I...
cherished you, Lwaxana.
You were my most
treasured possession.
Take care of our son.
When he asks...
speak well of me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please do me the honor
of accompanying me
to my humble establishment.
I'm throwing a party
for the happy couple.
Quark?
What can I say?
I'm a hopeless romantic.
Are you all right?
We did it.
He's really leaving.
It would appear so.
Oh, Odo, you were wonderful.
You know, for a minute there
I really believed you
wanted to marry me.
I suppose that we should
tell them the truth...
but let's wait
till after the party.
Jake, you should rest.
Not now.
I'm on to something.
Your father will be home soon.
You should be there.
I'll see him later.
Enough.
What'd you do that for?
You're pushing yourself
too hard.
No, I'm not.
My mind has never been so clear.
Everything is coming together.
At this rate, I can finish
this novel in a few days.
And you will.
I promise you.
But if you rest now,
your work will be even better.
All right.
I'll go home.
Maybe get some sleep.
You'll come back later?
Of course.
I need you.
Promenade.
Orange juice.
Something has stimulated
Jake's brain functioning in
a way that I have never seen.
The capillaries in his cerebral
cortex have dilated 20 percent.
Neurotransmitter production
is up by at least that amount
and neural activity
is off the scale.
Do you have any idea
what caused it?
Not yet, but it's a good thing
we got him here when we did.
His cortex was on the verge
of synaptic collapse.
But he is going to be all right.
Mm-hmm.
I'd like to keep him
in the neural stabilization
field for a while.
Onaya.
Jake.
Where is she?
Jake, what happened?
I'm going to talk to Odo
see if he knows anything
about this Onaya.
I'll let you know
if his condition changes.
I'll be in the lab.
Come with me, Jake.
It's time to finish...
what we started.
I'm picking up
concentrated traces
of some sort of psionic energy
in the bulkhead.
The tests I ran indicated
that Jake's mental activity
was stimulated by some kind
of psionic phenomenon
possibly telepathic in nature.
Then this entity
Nurse Tagana saw
could have been responsible.
We have to find it,
then get Jake back
in the neural stabilization
field before it's too late.
I'll tell Odo to have
his search parties
reconfigure their tricorders
to scan for psionic energy.
That'll help,
but only for a while.
Psionic residue
decays within minutes.
Then we'd better get moving.
Keep going, Jake.
The moment...
I saw you...
I knew you were worthy
of what I could give you.
But I can't stay
with you forever.
This is your chance...
to create something
that will live on
long after you're gone.
There...
it'll stop in a minute.
I'm getting something...
about 20 meters
in this direction.
I'll go this way.
You swing around
and take Tunnel 61-G.
What's wrong?
I-I can't...
Let me help you.
That's better, isn't it?
Get away from him!
Dad, don't... don't interfere.
I said get away!
Sisko to Ops.
Go ahead.
Lock on to my signal
and stand by to beam Jake
directly to the Infirmary.
You're too close
to the reactor core.
There's so much interference,
I can't get a lock.
Get a medical team
down here immediately.
Aye, sir.
What are you?
It's not what I am that matters.
It's what I do.
You don't know
the minds I've touched...
Catullus, Tarbolde, Keats...
a hundred others.
I unlocked their potential.
Is that what you did to Jake?
Look at him!
They all die in the end
but look what I gave them
in return... immortality.
Their names
will live on forever.
And you...
what do you get out of it?
What I need to survive,
so I can go on, find others
and unlock their talents
as well.
He was the youngest
I ever found.
So eager...
ready to give everything
he had in one great burst.
What a waste.
I will never forget you, Jake.
You're not going anywhere.
I have wonderful news.
There's a transport for Betazed
leaving this afternoon.
I'm going home.
I thought you were planning
on having the baby here.
If I did, I'd end up
staying for months
and that wouldn't be fair.
I've imposed on you enough.
Lwaxana...
you could deliver
at any time now
and it's a long way to Betazed.
You really should stay.
I'll miss you, too.
Then why leave?
You've gotten used
to having me around
haven't you?
Oh, you dear, sweet man.
Don't you see?
What you want is company,
someone to take care of.
Is that so wrong?
No, of course not.
The problem is, I want much
more than that from you.
You see, I can't help it.
I'm still in love with you.
And as much as I wish that
you were in love with me
I know you're not.
I could stay.
I could try to make you
fall in love with me
but we both know
that won't happen.
Then I'd end up resenting you
and our friendship
is far too important
for me to let that happen.
That's why it's better
for both of us
if I leave now.
Good-bye, husband.
Good-bye...
wife.
How are you feeling?
Okay, I guess.
You've read it?
I just finished.
What do you think?
You've got a good start
on a novel here, Jake.
The dialogue is sharp,
the story's involving
the characters are real.
The spelling is terrible.
I especially like the father.
Remind you of anyone?
A bit.
It's really good.
I know.
I just wish I wrote it.
You did.
How can I be sure?
I mean, without Onaya...
Listen to me.
You wrote these words, not her.
But she got them
out of me.
Which means they were somewhere
inside of you.
And all you have to do
is to learn to find
them for yourself.
You're right.
But I got to tell you.
I don't feel up to writing
just yet.
That's understandable.
Take it easy for a while.
You'll get back to it.
And then, someday...
when you're ready,
maybe you'll finish it.
Sounds like a plan.
I've got to get to work.
I'll check in on you
in a couple of hours.
I'll be here.