SISKO: Captain's Log,
Stardate 49904.2.
After driving away
Breen privateers
from the Bajoran colony
of Free Haven,
we are returning
to Deep Space 9.
When I was Lela Dax,
I went through the same thing.
Every night, I'd
tuck in my son Ahjess
and two hours later, he'd
crawl into bed with me.
I don't think I slept
through a night for weeks.
Weeks? Molly's been doing this
for two months already.
She just needs
a little attention.
Dax is right.
I'd say she's jealous.
She knows that you and Keiko
are going to have a baby soon.
What makes you
such an expert on children?
First in my class
in pediatric medicine.
I wouldn't sit there
if I were you.
Why? Miles spill
something again?
It's Worf's seat.
He'll be here in a minute.
Just because Worf
lives on the Defiant full-time
doesn't give him proprietary
rights in the Mess Hall.
No one says it does.
He just likes that seat.
Prune juice,
extra large.
Have a seat, Commander.
Thank you.
SISKO:
All senior staff, report
to the Bridge immediately.
( alarm blares )
You'd better have
a look at this.
( people yelling commands
and responses )
KIRA:
Concentrate on the fires
in Section 13.
We have to keep them away
from the plasma conduits.
Has anyone seen
my brother Rom?!
He told me he was
going to be working
in one of the upper
pylons today.
He's fine.
I saw him with one
of the damage-control teams
on Level 5.
Ah, what a relief.
Wait till I find him--
I'll kill him!
For scaring me
like this.
Major, here's a
preliminary list
of the stolen equipment.
SISKO:
Report, Major.
It was a Jem'Hadar
strike team.
They beamed aboard
from a civilian transport,
disabled communications
and weapons,
set off an explosive device
in Upper Pylon 3.
Fought a number
of small...
This one's gone.
Spinal fracture,
and severe trauma
to the cranial meninges.
They raided the Science Lab,
the reactor-control facility
and several cargo bays.
"Microfusion initiators,
photonic amplifiers,
EPS power
stabilizers."
They were out of here
and through the wormhole
before we knew what hit us.
BASHIR:
Constable, how many casualties
do we have?
So far, 18 confirmed dead,
31 missing,
and over a hundred wounded.
How long ago did
the Jem'Hadar leave?
Uh... 45 minutes
at the most.
That means their ion trail
hasn't decayed yet.
We could still follow them.
I intend to do
more than that.
Sisko to Defiant.
Prepare for departure.
I'm going to stay here,
take care of the wounded.
That includes you.
The station's yours, Major.
Contact Starfleet.
Tell them to get
some ships out here
just in case
this is a diversion.
Understood.
Constable, you're with us.
Sisko to Defiant.
Three to beam out.
What do you see, Dax?
Nothing good.
Their ion trail
is getting fainter.
The Jem'Hadar must be
emitting a magneton pulse
to cover their tracks.
Keep on them.
I want that ship.
Frankly, I'm surprised
something like this
hasn't happened sooner.
Being at the edge
of the wormhole
makes Deep Space 9
a tempting target.
Sometimes, I wish we
could have the Defiant
standing guard over the
station 26 hours a day.
Restricting the Defiant
to guard duty
would be
a serious mistake.
You wouldn't say that
if you had family
living in the station.
Perhaps, but adopting
a siege mentality
is ultimately
self-defeating.
I've got something.
Bearing 057 mark 009.
Red Alert.
On screen.
( alarm blares )
WORF:
A Jem'Hadar warship.
This cannot be the vessel
we are looking for.
Major Kira said
the Jem'Hadar strike team
that attacked the station
used a transport ship.
Captain, that warship's
in pretty bad shape.
Looks like someone's been using
it for target practice.
They're transmitting
a broad-band distress signal.
It could be a trap.
How many crew
members aboard?
I'm reading
seven life signs.
You won't be reading them
for long.
Their reactor's
about to go critical.
Chief, have a security detail
report to the transporter bay.
Odo, Commander Worf,
you're with me.
Transporter
protocol five.
Sisko to Bridge.
Drop cloak.
Engage.
SISKO:
Reinstate cloak.
If you're looking
for your weapons...
they were removed in transport.
Even without weapons...
we're more than
a match for you.
I would not be
so certain of that.
A Klingon.
And the traitor.
The Founders
will be pleased.
MALE:
Omet'iklan.
Control your men.
These people
saved our lives.
OMET'IKLAN:
And for that,
we shall take advantage
of their mistake.
You'll do nothing
without my approval.
My apologies, Captain.
I'm afraid the Jem'Hadar
are sadly deficient
in the social graces.
Two hours ago,
my station was attacked
by a Jem'Hadar strike team.
I know-- they
attacked us, too.
Why would your own people
attack you?
Tell them nothing.
This is not
their concern.
Your next allowance
of white will be in
two hours.
If you want it on time
you will be quiet
and do as you're told.
Captain...
you and I should talk...
in private?
If you have something
to say to me, make it quick.
Captain Benjamin Sisko.
I feel honored.
Your psychographic profile
is required reading
for Vorta Field Supervisors.
I probably know things about you
you don't know yourself.
If you're trying
to impress me,
you can forget it.
What would you say...
if I offered to make you
absolute ruler
of the Federation?
No President,
no Starfleet
Chief of Staff--
just you.
I'd say your psychographic
profile of me
isn't as good as you think.
( chuckling )
Just...
doing my job--
trying to build a bridge
between the Dominion
and a potential ally.
After all,
wouldn't it be much simpler
if the Dominion
and the Federation
could reach some mutual
beneficial understanding
without resorting
to the unpleasantness
of military conflict?
I want to know how to find
the Jem'Hadar
who attacked my station.
If you want to build a bridge,
why don't you start there?
I can lead you to them.
But... there's something
I need in exchange.
What's that?
I want you to help
me eliminate them.
The Jem'Hadar that
attacked your station
are renegades.
They've turned their back
on their oath of allegiance
to the Dominion
and it's my job to see
to it they're punished.
Why do you need my help?
You could send a fleet of
Jem'Hadar warships after them.
I'm afraid
we don't have the time.
Captain...
are you familiar
with the Iconians?
They controlled a vast
interstellar empire
about 200,000 years ago.
What's important
is how the Iconians
controlled that empire.
The gateways.
Exactly.
Sophisticated transporters
that allowed them
to move instantaneously
from one planet to another,
from one solar system to another
without the use of starships.
What does any of this
have to do with me?
Dominion scientists
recently discovered a gateway
on one of our outlying worlds.
We sent a team of scientists
to restore it,
but their Jem'Hadar guards
rebelled
and are now trying to complete
the gateway themselves.
These... renegade Jem'Hadar
stole some equipment
from my station--
EPS power stabilizers,
microfusion initiators,
photonic amplifiers.
I would say it's very possible
they're going
to use that equipment to help
them complete the gateway.
You...
understand
the nature of our dilemma.
If the Jem'Hadar are able
to make the gateway operational,
they'll become
virtually invincible.
Our experts predict
the renegades would gather
support
from other Jem'Hadar units,
launch a general insurrection
and effect a complete takeover
of the Dominion
in less than a year.
None of which
is my problem.
That's very short-sighted
of you, Captain.
Think about it.
If the Jem'Hadar seize
control of the Dominion,
there'll be
no stopping them.
Even shutting down
the wormhole
won't protect
the Alpha Quadrant.
With the gateway
they could put a million
Jem'Hadar warriors
on any Federation planet
instantaneously.
Would you care to see
our projections
of Federation casualties?
Couldn't the Founders
just order them
to surrender?
From what I know,
the Jem'Hadar have been
genetically engineered
to obey them.
The Founders' ability
to control the Jem'Hadar
has been somewhat...
overstated.
Otherwise, we never would have
had to addict them to the white.
Sounds like the Dominion
isn't quite as stable
as you'd like us to believe.
The Dominion has endured
for 2,000 years,
and will continue to endure
long after the Federation
has crumbled into dust.
But we'll leave
that to history.
Right now, we have
a more pressing concern.
The gateway must be destroyed.
Agreed?
Agreed.
So let me get this straight.
We're going to work
with the Jem'Hadar
to fight the Jem'Hadar.
I don't relish
this idea either,
but we don't have
much of a choice.
I was on the mission
that discovered
the Iconian homeworld.
We were forced to destroy
the gateway we found there
rather than let it fall
into the hands of the Romulans
and Starfleet Command
supported our decision.
If they didn't want the Romulans
to get a hold of it
I'm sure they don't want the
Jem'Hadar to have it either.
What are we supposed to do?
Give Omet'iklan and his men
their weapons back
and then hope
they don't point them at us?
They're not
going to get
their hands on any weapons
until we reach our target.
How do we know that these
Jem'Hadar can be trusted?
They must realize
that controlling the gateway
would mean freedom
for their people.
According to Weyoun,
they don't know anything
about the gateway.
They think that this
is just a routine
search-and-destroy mission--
find the renegade Jem'Hadar,
eliminate them
and their base.
You are asking us to lie
to them about our mission.
It is not honorable.
O'BRIEN:
There's a lot of things
about this mission
that bother me.
But lying to the Jem'Hadar
is not on top of my list.
If the Jem'Hadar find out
that we've deceived them...
They're not going
to find out anything.
Well, they won't hear it
from me.
There'll be a joint
briefing session at 1900 hours.
Followed by a get-to-know-you
buffet at 1930.
And I forgot my dress uniform.
( door chimes )
Enter.
You requested my presence.
It seems we're going
to be working together.
So I'm told.
Luckily for you,
the only thing I despise
more than the Federation
is a Jem'Hadar soldier
who breaks his vow
of allegiance.
I'm glad you see it that way.
Now-- I have a few things
I want to make clear.
First, this is my ship
and my command,
which means I give the orders,
not you and not Weyoun.
What's more, I'm holding you
personally responsible
for the actions of your men.
If I have a problem with them,
you're the one who's going
to have to answer for it.
That's as it should be.
After all--
I'm the First.
As far as I'm concerned,
on this mission, I'm the First.
Until the traitors are found
and terminated.
After that...
we shall see.
Am I dismissed?
For the time being.
SISKO:
According to Dominion
Intelligence, the Jem'Hadar
have established
a base camp here.
The interior of the structure
is riddled with a
network of corridors
and interlocking chambers.
Our primary objective
is to destroy the Jem'Hadar arms
and supply cache
in this chamber.
The trick...
will be getting there.
We can't beam directly
into the structure,
which means we'll have
to fight our way in.
Jem'Hadar tactics
dictate
at least 27 soldiers
are stationed
inside the base camp
at all times.
Nine will patrol
the perimeter.
And additional troops are
deployed throughout the city.
How many renegades are there
altogether?
162 in the original garrison.
We killed at least 12
during the initial rebellion.
Well, that still
leaves 150.
Just between you and me,
Captain, I think we're
a little outnumbered.
Wouldn't it be simpler
to take out the
base from orbit?
A couple of quantum torpedoes
should be enough to
level the entire area.
Unfortunately,
that's not an option.
The central structure
is composed of
solid neutronium.
Even a direct hit
from a quantum torpedo
wouldn't necessarily
destroy our objective.
Which means we have
to go in ourselves.
JEM'HADAR:
As it should be.
It is our duty to punish
those who would break
their vow of loyalty.
Are you accusing me
of something?
OMET'IKLAN:
It is not for us
to accuse a god
of betraying heaven.
The gods themselves...
will sit in judgment over you.
I'm no god,
and neither
are the Founders.
The sooner you realize that,
the better off you'll be.
We've chosen
a beam-in site here
in this wooded area.
That'll give us a chance
to evaluate the situation
before proceeding.
Our first objective will be
to secure the main entrance
to the ziggurat.
Neutralizing nine guards
before one of them
can raise an alarm
will be difficult.
It's as you said.
The Klingon will to fight
pales in comparison
to our own.
Yes.
He has the look
of a warrior,
but the heart
of a coward.
If you would like to
test my courage, I--
All right, that's enough.
One day,
the Klingon Empire
will fall before the Jem'Hadar,
and when that day comes,
and piles of Klingons
lie dead at my feet,
I will think of you,
standing here,
impotent and weak,
and I will laugh.
All right! I said that's enough!
Worf, let him go!
Second!
Release the Klingon,
or I will kill you
where you stand.
Now, the two of you,
as you were.
I promise, you'll both
have more fight
than you can handle
before this is over.
( grunts )
Let's go.
I'm right with you.
Worf!
Go.
Ready.
Wait.
The room's not secure.
We have to find the third guard.
I do not see him.
He's here somewhere.
I know.
We're supposed to be
on our way out
by now.
Where is he?
We're running
out of time, Commander.
The third
Jem'Hadar guard--
he is still
here somewhere.
Look for a slight
rippling effect.
We know what
we're looking for.
We just can't find it.
We're dead.
OMET'IKLAN:
That's correct.
WEYOUN:
The Jem'Hadar defense grid
is now in operation.
Automated weapon systems
have killed everyone
in this room.
Your crew failed
in their mission.
Well, you might as well tell us,
where's the other one?
There was
no third guard.
I don't understand.
You told me
that Jem'Hadar soldiers
always operate
in teams of three.
In battle,
nothing is certain.
You should have
armed the explosives
as soon as you
were in position.
We had to be sure
the room was secured.
Otherwise, someone
could have
disarmed the explosives
the moment we left.
OMET'IKLAN:
If you couldn't secure the room
you should not plan
on leaving it.
You want us to blow the place up
while we're still in it?
This is a waste of time.
They'll never succeed
as long as they value
their lives more than victory.
There's something
to be said for soldiers
who aren't afraid to die.
Oh, I don't know.
I've found that
nothing keeps me alert
quite like a healthy
fear of death.
Keep practicing.
The two of
you, with me.
One of the reasons
for these drills
is to help our crews
learn to work together.
Constantly showing
contempt for my people
isn't making
it any easier.
Would you prefer I lied?
What I'd like
is for you to at least
maintain the pretense
that we're on the same side.
Captain, I understand
your concerns,
and so does Omet'iklan.
Deck Five, Section One.
The only way
my troops
can come to
respect your crew
is to fight alongside them--
mixed teams
in every aspect
of the mission.
That's not practical.
Why not?
Are you questioning my decision?
You fool.
My men and I,
we know all about the gateway.
Halt turbolift.
Looks like your secret's out.
How do you know
about the gateway?
It doesn't matter
how we know.
The point is, we know.
You think you have to lie to us
and use the white
to ensure our loyalty.
But the fact is, we are
more loyal to the Founders
than the Vorta
ever will be.
It is the reason
for our existence.
It is the core...
of our being.
There's an entire company
of Jem'Hadar
down on Vandros IV
who would disagree with you.
And for that, they will die.
Mixed teams, it is.
But let's get
one thing straight.
This isn't going to be
a suicide mission.
As far as I'm concerned,
everyone who goes in,
comes back out--
Starfleet and Jem'Hadar alike.
Your concern for life
is touching.
Let's hope it doesn't stop us
from achieving...
our objectives.
Computer, reactivate turbolift.
Am I really
that interesting?
You've been standing
there staring at me
for the last two hours.
You are part of
my combat team.
I must learn to understand
your behavior,
anticipate
your actions.
There must be something
you'd rather do.
Maybe get some sleep?
We don't sleep.
How about getting
something to eat?
The white is
the only thing we need.
You don't sleep,
you don't eat.
What do you do for relaxation?
Relaxation
would only make us weak.
Well, you people
are no fun at all.
I'm glad I'm not
a Jem'Hadar woman.
There are no Jem'Hadar women.
So what do you do?
Lay eggs?
Jem'Hadar are bred
in birthing chambers.
We are able to fight within
three days of our emergence.
Lucky you.
So let me get this straight.
No sleep, no food...
no women.
No wonder you're so angry.
After 30 or 40 years of that,
I'd be angry, too.
No Jem'Hadar
has ever lived 30 years.
How old are you?
I am eight.
I would have guessed
at least 15.
Hmm. Few Jem'Hadar
live that long.
If we reach 20,
we are considered
honored elders.
How old are you?
I stopped counting at 300.
You don't look it.
Thank you.
No women?
I'm not surprised.
Personally,
I envy them.
I mean, their ability
to go without sleep.
I'm sure I could
be more productive
if I didn't have to
regenerate every day.
What is the point
of doing battle
if you cannot enjoy
the fruits of your victory?
You mean sleep?
No, I mean spending long nights
singing songs of your deeds.
Good food, good drink.
And good women.
Now, we consider Klingon women
our partners in battle.
They are the mothers
of our children.
And a lot of fun
at parties, too.
True.
( chuckling )
Why does he keep staring at us?
I don't think it's us
he's staring at.
I think it's you.
DAX:
The Vorta
probably consider
the Founders gods just
like the Jem'Hadar do.
I am not a Founder.
Well, you're
a changeling.
That's close enough.
To them.
I wonder what would happen
if you went over there
and ordered him
to stand on his head.
( laughing )
It's time.
It is time
when I say
it's time.
( groans )
Very well.
Prepare six vials.
Unlock.
First Omet'iklan,
can you vouch
for the loyalty
of your men?
We pledge our loyalty
to the Founders
from now until death.
Then receive this reward
from the Founders.
May it keep you strong.
I guess that's one way
to assure loyalty.
Loyalty bought at such a price
is no loyalty at all.
Resume your training.
Human, come with me.
It is time to resume
our battle drills.
In a minute.
I'm ready now.
Well, I'm not.
They stuff themselves
with food
but have no appetite
for battle.
When the time comes, you
will find us more than ready.
Ready to flee
at the first sign of danger.
Let's go.
You can practice
running away.
I've always wanted
to kill a Klingon.
That's enough!
The next one
who throws a punch
will have to answer to me!
Now, I want to know
who started this!
I did.
And I.
You...
again.
You knew my orders.
And I defied them.
I deserve punishment.
And you shall have it.
Why are you waiting?
Kill him
and be done with it.
Mr. Worf...
when not on duty,
you are confined to quarters
for the remainder
of this mission.
Yes, sir.
All right, let's
break this up.
Get back to your stations
or to your quarters.
Either way, I want
this room cleared.
Now!
You call that discipline?
A dead man can't learn
from his mistakes.
I don't get the same joy
out of killing as you do.
You think I enjoyed it?
Toman'torax was my Second.
He served under me three years.
I valued him.
You have a...
funny way of showing it.
I did what had to be done--
what any First
would do.
I placed the good
of the unit
above my personal feelings.
Any soldier
who cannot follow orders
is a danger to his unit...
and must be eliminated.
Mr. Worf is not a danger
to my command.
But if I eliminate him for
a simple breach of discipline,
then I would be.
My men would stop trusting me,
and I wouldn't blame them.
You are weak.
You should die in his place.
And when this
mission is over,
I will see that you do.
Odo.
May I speak with
you for a moment?
A moment.
You... know I've
been watching you.
I've noticed.
I have to admit,
I find it somewhat
disturbing seeing you
working for these...
Federation people...
letting them
order you around.
You are a Founder.
You should be the one
giving the orders to them,
to the Jem'Hadar
or even me.
So... if I order you
to leave me alone,
you will?
Of course.
But before you do,
please, hear
what I have to say.
Your people want you
to come home, Odo.
No matter
what differences
you may have
with them,
no matter what mistakes
you may have made,
they still love you.
Well, maybe they do...
but I don't love them.
You're lying,
and you're not very good at it.
I, on the other hand,
am an expert at lies--
both in telling them
and in spotting them.
So you may as well
admit the truth.
More than anything
in your life...
you want to return
to your people.
And I can make that possible.
How?
Let me worry about the "how."
All I need to know is...
are you ready to go home?
No.
But I am ready to end
this conversation.
Then it's over.
After all, you are a Founder.
I live to serve you.
Commander?
For Keiko?
It's my 11th good-bye message
since we've been married.
I'm averaging
almost two a year.
Does she know you do this?
What would I say to her?
"You know, honey,
"every time I'm about
to go into battle,
"I record a message
for you and Molly,
telling you how much
I love you, just in case."
She'd probably
think it was sweet.
It'd probably scare
the hell out of her.
To be honest,
it scares the hell out of me.
Every time I record
one of these, I think,
"This is it.
This is the one they're
going to end up hearing."
It'll never happen.
What makes you say that?
Because when you've lived
eight lifetimes,
you develop certain instincts.
And my instincts tell me
that you, Miles Edward O'Brien,
are going to live to be 140
and die in bed,
surrounded by family
and friends.
Do you really believe that?
Do you?
I'd like to.
That's all that matters.
Well, just to be
on the safe side,
maybe you'd better enter this
in the ship's log anyway.
I'll put it right alongside
my message to my mother.
You record these, too?
Doesn't everyone?
Sir.
Well, it looks like
the upgraded reactant injectors
are working better
than we thought.
Captain.
Mr. Worf.
Battle drills ended
ten minutes ago.
You should be
in your quarters.
I'm on my way.
It looks like you
got a little lost.
There is something
I wish to discuss with you.
Go on.
It has come to my attention
that First Omet'iklan
has threatened to kill you.
I didn't know that
was public knowledge.
You told Commander Dax.
Well, that explains it.
She is concerned about you,
and for good reason.
As your Executive Officer,
I recommend that you
remain on the ship
during the away mission.
That way, Omet'iklan
will have no opportunity
to carry out his threat.
I appreciate the concern,
but do you really think
I'm going to follow
that recommendation?
No, sir, I do not.
But I hope you
will take some advice.
Do not turn your back on him.
I won't.
Good.
I also want you to know,
if somehow he does carry out
his threat...
he will not live
to boast about it.
That's... very reassuring,
Mr. Worf.
Dax to Sisko.
Go ahead.
We're approaching Vandros IV.
Captain.
On my way.
I'm waiting.
Don't worry.
These aren't like the ones
we gave you
during the drill.
They're fully charged.
The weapon's set on "stun."
Deactivate safeties.
Reset weapons...
to maximum power.
Well, this is a
momentous occasion--
the first joint
operation between
the Federation
and the Dominion.
I can't wait to see
how it turns out.
Prepare to transport.
Wait.
I am First
Omet'iklan.
And I am dead.
As of this moment,
we are all dead.
We go into battle...
to reclaim our lives.
This we do gladly,
for we are Jem'Hadar.
Remember--
victory is life.
JEM'HADAR:
Victory is life.
Such a delightful people.
I am Chief Miles
Edward O'Brien.
I'm very much alive,
and I intend
to stay that way.
Amen.
Let's get it done.
You betrayed us.
What are you
talking about?
Our rifles
are sabotaged.
Hold on.
Mine's dead, too.
Something must be interfering
with our equipment.
The gateway.
It's probably generating
some kind of dampening field.
If that's the case,
we'd better come up
with a new plan.
( yells in pain )
( Jem'Hadar grunting )
( groans )
We lost Ramirez, too.
It would appear
we no longer have
the element
of surprise.
I suppose
you want
to call off
the mission.
Guess again.
Worf.
This way.
Go ahead.
We'll hold them off.
( yells )
Keep moving.
Virak'kara,
are you still there?!
For a little while longer.
Don't worry!
You'll make honored...
elder... yet.
JEM'HADAR:
Down that way!
Look down that hall.
Over there.
I think we have waited
long enough.
( all grunt )
You're sure
the explosives
won't be affected
by the gateway?
The primary detonator
might not work,
but the chemical backup
should do the trick.
The way is clear.
Let's move.
( yells )
( groaning )
I threatened to kill you,
but you were willing
to sacrifice yourself
to save my life.
Looks that way.
Why?
If you have to ask,
you'll never understand.
O'BRIEN:
Gentlemen,
I think it's time
we were leaving.
( explosive beeping rapidly )
Let's go.
If I were you,
I'd run like hell.
What about Dax
and the others?
WORF:
Here, Captain.
( explosion )
So much for the gateway.
Our weapons are
working again.
The Defiant's sensors
registered a powerful explosion
in the vicinity of the gateway.
I trust your mission
was a success?
The gateway's been destroyed,
if that's what you mean.
( laughing )
Well done, Captain.
You've all done
quite nicely.
Now, if you
don't mind,
I'd like to inspect
the wreckage.
That was for questioning...
our loyalty.
I think
there's been enough
killing for one day.
The Vorta will have
no further use of this.
My men and I
will remain here.
There are still disloyal
Jem'Hadar on this planet.
They must be hunted down
and eliminated.
Good luck.
You fought well.
But the next time we meet...
we'll be enemies.
I'll keep that in mind.
I don't know about the rest
of you, but I'd like
to get out of here.
Sisko to Defiant.
Begin transport.