You wanted to
see me, Garak?
Ah! Constable.
How good of you
to stop by.
A shoplifter?
Excuse me?
Is something wrong?
WOMAN:
Here I come.
What do you think?
"A thing of beauty
is a joy forever."
Oh, well, then
put it on my account.
I'll wear it to work.
A splendid idea.
Ah. Security Chief Odo
I'd like to introduce you
to Chalan Aroya--
one of my best customers.
I own the Celestial Cafe--
the new Bajoran restaurant
overlooking the Promenade?
I-I'm familiar with it.
I watch you walk by
every morning
when you're on patrol.
0937.
You're very precise.
How... nice of
you to notice.
I was hoping
one day
you might stop in
when you're not working.
Uh... I don't eat.
I do
and I hate to eat alone.
Think about it.
Oh, and next time you're
on the Second Level
don't forget to say hello.
The next time you call me
it had better be
to report a crime.
Now that you mention it,
I've just witnessed a crime:
Letting Aroya
walk out of here
without arranging a date.
You should be locked away
for that.
You humanoids--
you're all obsessed
with these convoluted
mating rituals.
True, but do you think
we'd waste
so much time on something
that wasn't worthwhile?
I'll never understand you.
You're such a sensitive man
yet there are so many aspects
of humanoid life
that you simply refuse
to explore.
I have no desire
to become a slave
to humanoid obsessions.
But you have
to admit
she is quite lovely.
Well... she is, isn't she?
Mm-hmm.
Oh!
( groaning )
Odo!
What's wrong?
I... I don't know.
( yelling in pain )
Garak to Dr. Bashir.
I need a medical
emergency team
sent to my shop
immediately.
Doctor, this is a waste of time.
You don't know enough
about changeling physiology
to diagnose what's wrong
with me, no one does.
Actually, I do have
some idea what's going on.
I've compared
your current medical scans
with ones I made
over the last four years
and there are
some noticeable differences.
Normally, when you're
in humanoid form
you have a specific
density of 1.4
which is constant
throughout your body.
Your mass and density only vary
when you change shape.
Right now, your mass and density
are in a state of fluctuation.
Do you know what's causing it?
No.
Well, do you know
how to prevent it
from happening again?
Not yet.
Well, then let me know
when you do.
I'm afraid I can't
let you leave just yet.
Moving seems to increase
the fluctuations
and may bring on
another attack.
Are you saying
I have to stay here
until you discover a cure?
Or until the fluctuations
stop on their own.
For all I know
this could be a normal
biological process--
the changeling
equivalent of puberty...
or menopause.
That's an interesting
theory, Doctor--
one I suggest
that you keep to yourself.
Don't worry.
This could just as easily
turn out to be a virus
or a bacterial infection.
Now, lie back, and I promise
I'll do everything I can
to get you out of here
as soon as possible.
( sigh of disgust )
( sighing )
We find the Federation's demands
that we return
the captured Cardassian colonies
insulting and provocative.
Klingon blood was spilled
to conquer those worlds.
They are now part
of the Klingon Empire
and we will never give them up.
Furthermore, if the Federation
still harbors any hope
of peaceful coexistence
with the Klingon Empire
it must abandon all starbases
and military installations
in the Archanis sector.
Our claim to Archanis IV
and the surrounding territory
is ancient and indisputable.
We advise the Federation
to leave Archanis
or prepare to face
the consequences.
Long live the Empire.
This recording was sent
to the Federation Council
three days ago.
If Gowron is willing to go to
war over the Archanis sector
then he has become even more
dangerous than I thought.
I don't get it.
The Klingons relinquished
their claim to Archanis IV
a hundred years ago.
I guess
they changed their mind.
I don't think Gowron
gives a damn about Archanis.
He's just looking for an excuse
to rattle his saber.
The question is why.
Yesterday, I talked to
an old friend of Curzon's
from the diplomatic corps.
She says
that representatives
from Federation worlds
near the Klingon border
are already urging
a preemptive strike.
Sounds like war
may be inevitable.
I hope you're wrong, Major,
but right now, there's not much
we can do about it either way.
Archanis IV
is a long way from here.
( sneezing )
Two, three...
I say she stops
at seven.
I say eight.
Mr. Worf?
Ten.
Oh, I hate being pregnant!
I win.
My nose hasn't
stopped itching for weeks.
DAX:
We've noticed.
Is there anything
Dr. Bashir can do about it?
I'm Bajoran. Human women
get nauseous-- we sneeze.
Besides, I think Dr. Bashir's
hands are full right now.
How is
the Constable?
No news yet.
I was thinking
about going to visit him.
I doubt that he
would wish to be seen
in such a weakened state.
What if he wants
some company--
someone to take his
mind off his problems?
That is doubtful.
Odo values his privacy.
He does not like
to... socialize.
I think it's
all an act.
It is not an act.
He told me so himself.
But you were
socializing with him
when he said it.
Captain,
was Dax's last host
as argumentative
as this one?
Worse.
Thank you, Benjamin...
I think.
Hopefully, Odo will get
back on his feet soon.
In the meantime, I want him
left alone to rest. Agreed?
( Kira sneezing )
Agreed.
May I come in?
If you're looking
for Dr. Bashir
he's not in right now.
Actually,
I came to see you.
To be honest, Major
I really don't feel like
company at the moment.
I didn't plan on staying.
I just came
to bring you this.
Today's criminal
activities report.
I figured you might
be getting tired
of staring at
medical consoles all day.
That was very thoughtful
of you, Major.
If there's anything
else you need
you let me know.
Yeah. I-I'll do that.
What?
( grunting )
Ah...
ah.
Keep moving.
I'll feel a lot better
once we're off this station.
ODO:
Too bad
because you're not leaving.
Security Chief Odo.
I heard
you were indisposed.
Well, you heard wrong.
Now, you and I
need to talk
about those missing
Falangian diamonds.
I told you before
I don't know anything
about them.
Well, tell me again.
Oh, no, you don't.
( yelling in pain )
Let's go.
How are you feeling?
See for yourself.
It's gotten worse.
Very observant, Doctor.
It's been more
and more difficult
for me to maintain
humanoid form.
The latest test results
aren't encouraging.
The destabilization
of your molecular structure
is increasing
at an alarming rate.
How much longer before I totally
lose my ability to stay solid?
One week, maybe two.
After that, if
the destabilization continues...
Ah.
I sent my findings
to, uh, Dr. Mora.
Frankly,
he was as baffled as I am,
but he wants you to come
to his laboratory on Bajor
for further tests.
( snorts )
Seven years of playing lab rat
for him was quite enough.
Besides, you have
complete access to his data.
If the answer was there,
you'd have found it by now.
I don't suppose
you'd agree
on a trip to Starfleet Medical.
Doctor...
I think we both know
where I have to go.
I was hoping
it wouldn't come to that.
There doesn't seem to be
much choice.
You have to take me
back to my people.
The only ones
who can help me now
are the Founders.
Once we enter the Gamma Quadrant
we'll begin transmitting
a subspace signal
explaining the purpose
of our mission.
Then we'll enter
Dominion space
and try to locate
the Founders' new homeworld.
Odo's only got
a few weeks at best.
You think we can locate
his people in time?
If we go into
Dominion air space
without cloaking, we'll
get their attention.
You can be sure of that.
I'd like
to come along.
I don't think
so, Major.
I know Odo's your friend,
but I need you here. Besides...
( sneezes )
I know, I know.
When will you leave?
Doctor?
As soon as possible.
We'll prepare the Defiant.
You prepare the Constable.
All systems are ready
for departure.
Thank you, Mr. O'Brien.
The Medical Bay's all set
but it'll take a little while
to get Odo on board.
Why not use
the transporter?
Well, his molecular structure
is scrambled enough as it is.
The last thing he needs
is a trip through a
transporter buffer.
Benjamin, someone's
requesting permission
to come on board.
Who is it?
Garak.
Tell him the ship
is off limits
to Cardassian spies.
Sir, if Garak
is asking to come aboard
I'm sure he has
a good reason.
Have Mr. Garak
escorted to the mess hall.
I'll meet him there.
Personally,
I think Starfleet
should allow their officers
more latitude
in accessorizing
their uniforms, hmm?
You'd be surprised
what a nice scarf can do.
Ah, Captain,
how good of you to see me.
Make it brief, Garak.
I'd like to accompany you
on your mission.
There are some questions
I'd like to ask the Founders.
Such as?
The Cardassian Empire
lost a number of warships
during their aborted attack
on the Dominion.
I want to know what happened
to the crew members.
I was under the impression
that those ships
were destroyed
with all hands.
Oh, we don't know that
for a fact.
As I recall,
when the Defiant
left the scene of the battle,
there were a number
of Cardassian warships
still fighting.
Ah, and you think some
of their crew members
might have been
taken prisoner.
I live in hope.
Besides, if you do
take me along,
I think you'll find me
quite useful.
I'm a man
of many talents.
I have no need for a
tailor on this mission
let alone a spy...
but maybe there
is something
you can do for me.
This is going to be
a long trip for Odo.
I need someone to
occupy his attention,
take his mind off
his condition.
You want me
to keep him company.
No.
Anyone can do that--
Dax, Bashir, myself.
And what would we
have to offer him?
Kindness, sympathy.
That's the last
thing he wants.
But where you offer kindness,
I offer mystery.
Where you offer sympathy,
I offer intrigue.
Just give me a seat
next to Odo's bed
and I promise you I'll
conjure up enough innuendoes,
half-truths
and bald-faced lies
about my so-called career
in the Obsidian Order
to keep the Constable
distracted for days.
If there's one thing
Cardassians excel at
it's conversation.
You've got yourself a job.
But all questions
for the Founders
will have to wait until after
Odo gets the help he needs.
We share the same priorities,
Captain.
Make sure you remember that.
( groaning )
QUARK:
Odo...
Not now, Quark.
I'm busy.
I hear you're taking
a little trip
to the Gamma Quadrant.
Care to come along?
Are you kidding?
I expect to own this station
by the time you get back.
With you gone
profits from smuggling alone
should go up 60 percent.
Well, don't get used to it.
I'll be back before you know it
making your life miserable.
Then you are coming back.
Count on it.
I will.
Take your time.
I promise the Defiant
won't leave without you.
Would you
like me
to have the
Promenade cleared?
That won't be necessary.
We've just cleared
the wormhole.
Begin transmitting
a request for assistance.
Then set a course
for the Dominion.
Aye, sir.
It's funny.
I've served on
half a dozen ships
and none of them have
had cloaking devices
except the Defiant.
Now that we're not
using it, I feel naked.
It is disconcerting,
to say the least.
Gentlemen, I feel the
same breeze you do.
What are you smiling at?
I don't know.
I guess it's just
being in the same room
with so many naked men.
Ah, yes, the assassination
of Proconsul Merrok of Romulus.
Such a tragedy.
I met him once,
a few weeks before he died.
I was working as a gardener
at the Cardassian Embassy
during the...
You were a gardener
on Romulus?
My specialty
was Edosian orchids.
Beautiful,
but highly toxic.
As I recall
Proconsul Merrok was poisoned.
Funny... I don't remember that,
but then again,
so many Romulan dignitaries
died unexpectedly
that year.
Must be hard
to keep them
all straight.
Oh, you can't imagine.
Maybe
we should let the
Constable get some rest.
I'll let you know
when I need rest, Doctor.
A gardener... at the Cardassian
Embassy on Romulus?
Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
Fascinating.
So I get off duty
the other night
and I walk into
my quarters
and there's Keiko
and Major Kira talking.
Go on.
As soon as I walked
in, they stopped.
It was like turning off
a holosuite program.
They did not want you
to hear what they were saying.
Exactly, but I think they
were talking about me.
SISKO:
Come on, Chief.
You have no way of knowing that.
Oh, I may not have the proof
but I know one thing--
Molly was there
and when she saw me,
she started giggling.
( laughing )
Laugh all you want.
I'm thinking of asking Julian
to come live with us.
Even things up a little.
( console beeping )
Hold on. I'm reading warp
signatures headed our way.
It looks like our signal's
finally getting
a little attention.
Full stop. On screen.
Make that a lot of attention.
We're being hailed.
They want to beam someone aboard
to discuss our request.
I would advise
against allowing
Dominion representatives
aboard this ship.
It might be better to negotiate
over the viewscreen.
But I don't want
to give them any reason
to think
that we're hiding something.
Odo needs their help and I'm
going to make sure he gets it.
Commander, tell the Jem'Hadar
that I'll meet
their representative
in the transport bay.
Aye, sir.
( screams )
That's enough.
Let him go.
Please, everyone.
Lower your weapons.
There's no need for violence.
Are you okay?
I've felt better.
I've come for Odo.
Can you help him?
Only the Great Link
can help him.
Leave him with me
and you may return home
unharmed.
I can't do that.
A Founder has given you
an order.
You will obey it.
I'll let you know
when I need you.
I understand
your concern for Odo.
I feel it, too.
Then let's not stand here
and argue.
Just tell us
where we need to take him.
The faster we get moving,
the better off he'll be.
Your loyalty to Odo
is commendable.
I will not stop you
from accompanying him
on the rest of his journey.
However, I am sure
you understand my reluctance
to reveal the location
of our new home.
Commander, I must ask you
to surrender the helm.
Amat'igan will
guide your ship
for the remainder
of the voyage.
Captain?
My terms
are not open to negotiation.
Commander, give
him your seat.
This will prevent
your navigational computers
from retaining any record
of our journey.
Sir...
Not now, Mr. Worf.
FOUNDER:
There, that's better.
Now, Captain,
if it's not too much trouble
I would like
to pay Odo a visit.
How do I look, Doctor?
Does it matter?
Of course it matters.
I'm here as
a representative
of the Cardassian Empire
and I want to make
a good first impression.
Constable, what
do you think?
I think the Romulans
poisoned Proconsul Merrok
and you were the one responsible
for the transporter accident
that killed Subcommander Ustard.
You're getting warmer,
but how do I look?
( groans )
( door opens )
May I come in?
You'll pardon me
if I don't get up.
Poor Odo...
look what's become of you.
Not a pretty sight, am I?
Pretty?
I wasn't aware
you applied such value
to your outward appearance.
Such concerns are
more fitting for solids.
Excuse me, I, um,
don't mean to interrupt
but is there anything
you can do for him?
Odo...
give me your hand.
Don't be afraid.
( groaning )
Amazing.
Feeling better?
Yes, though I still
have to concentrate
to hold my form.
Your molecular structure
is still fluctuating,
but it's nowhere near
as unstable as it was.
Leave now.
I wish to speak
to Odo in private.
Odo is my... patient.
It's all right,
Doctor.
Then I'll
be right outside.
It can wait, Garak.
Of course.
What we have to say
is not for your ears.
Wait for me outside.
I wish this meeting were
under better circumstances.
Hmm. I'm not exactly thrilled
with the circumstances myself.
I had hoped that you'd
return to us on your own.
After all, that Bajoran woman
you were so fond of
seems to have taken
an interest in someone else.
You know about Major Kira
and First Minister Shakaar.
Despite your
rejection of us
we still take an active interest
in your well-being.
And just how do you
keep so informed
about my well-being?
There's very little
that escapes our attention.
Are you saying that
you knew I was sick
even before we
left the station?
What do you think?
( sighs )
I think you did this to me.
You caused my illness
so that I'd be forced
to come home.
As I said
I wish the circumstances
of this meeting were different.
You killed
a changeling, Odo.
He was trying
to kill my friends.
I had no choice.
Of course you had a choice
and you chose to side
with the solids.
To protect them,
you were willing to violate
the most sacred law
of our people.
No changeling has ever
harmed another.
Until you.
That's why
we forced you to return home...
to enter the Great Link
and be judged.
What does that mean,
I'm going to be judged?
You will join us
in the Great Link,
open your thoughts,
allow us to understand you.
Only then will we
be able to decide
whether your actions
were justified.
And if you decide
that they weren't?
You will be punished.
Punished how?
You have to understand
that nothing like this
has ever happened
in the entire history
of our people.
We have never had
to sit in judgment
over one of our own.
That's why we took so long
to bring you home.
There was... disagreement
in the Link
over what to do with you.
I'm sorry I've caused you
so much trouble.
Perhaps we are to blame.
We sent you away.
But I'm the one
who's going to be punished.
That remains to be seen.
What if I refuse to cooperate?
What if I...
refuse to join the Link?
I stabilized
your condition temporarily.
Only the Link can heal you.
If you refuse to join with us,
you will die.
You may go in now, Doctor.
Thank you.
Try not to disturb him.
He needs his rest.
I'll bear that
in mind.
Excuse me, madam.
May I have
a moment of your time?
You are Cardassian.
That's right,
and on behalf of my people
I'd like to learn
if there were any survivors
after our attack
on your homeland.
Cardassian survivors?
Yes.
There were no
Cardassian survivors.
You mean... they're all dead?
They're dead.
You're dead.
Cardassia is dead.
Your people were doomed
the moment they attacked us.
I believe
that answers your question.
It was a pleasure meeting you.
O'BRIEN:
I don't suppose
there's any way
Odo could hide a
communicator on him
when he's in the Link
with the Founders.
I do not think he'll be
able to hide anything
from the Founders.
There must be
some way we can keep
a transporter lock on him
while he's in the Link.
What about injecting him
with radio-nuclides?
Well, that would give
the transporter
something to lock onto,
but there's no way
to be sure the nuclides
won't disperse
throughout the Link.
If he's in there for more than
a few hours, we could end up
with a transporter pad
full of shape-shifters.
ODO:
I wouldn't worry
about that, Chief.
SISKO:
Constable, shouldn't you
be in bed?
He insisted on coming
to see you himself.
ODO:
I thought you might
be trying to help me
and I wanted to say
don't bother.
O'BRIEN:
Odo, surely you
don't expect us
to just stand by
while they do God
knows what to you.
That is exactly what I expect.
Captain, I want to be judged.
I'm the only changeling
who's ever harmed another.
I've spent most of my life
bringing people to justice.
Now that it's my turn,
how can I run away?
Are you sure
that's what you'll find
in the Great Link-- justice?
I've heard
lots of stories
about the Dominion
and the Founders
and justice seems to be
the last thing
on their minds.
Nevertheless, they're my people
and I intend
to accept their judgment.
Report.
Everything's
status quo.
If you want
more details than that
you'll have to ask
our navigator.
How much longer?
You'll be informed
when we reach our destination.
We will be within
transporter range
of my world in
less than an hour.
After we have achieved orbit
Odo and I
will transport to the surface.
Dr. Bashir and I
will be joining you.
If you wish,
but Odo may be
in the Link for days.
We'll wait.
Come, Odo.
It's time.
How long
has it been?
I've lost track.
So have I.
Doctor...
Oh...
oh...
right.
( sighs )
Wait here.
Garak.
Just as I thought.
Don't tell me.
I overlooked one
of the security monitors.
You were trying to override
the launch controls
for the quantum torpedoes.
I was hoping to gain control
of the phasers as well.
I just hadn't got
around to it yet.
Don't you see?
We have
an opportunity here--
a chance to end
the Dominion threat
once and for all.
We have enough firepower
on this ship
to turn that planet
into a smoking cinder.
Personally, I think that
would be a very good thing.
And what about Odo
and Captain Sisko
and Dr. Bashir?
They'll die.
And once the Jem'Hadar ships
realize what we're doing,
so will we.
But what are our lives
compared to saving
the entire Alpha Quadrant?
We are not here to wage war.
I'm not talking about war.
What I'm proposing is wiping out
every Founder on that planet--
obliterating the Great Link.
Come now, Mr. Worf,
you're a Klingon.
Don't tell me you'd object
to a little genocide
in the name of self-defense.
I am a warrior,
not a murderer.
What you are
is a great disappointment.
You fight well...
for a tailor.
Doctor.
( groaning )
Odo, are you all right?
Captain, I'm getting
some strange readings.
What have you done to him?
He has been judged.
Captain...
I'm reading a heart,
lungs...
and a digestive system.
It's as if he
were... human.
We gave him
what he wanted.
We made him a solid.
He's one of you now.
Oh...poor Odo.
Perhaps we should
have killed you.
It would have been
far less cruel.
He's yours.
Take him and go.
Sisko to Defiant.
DAX:
Go ahead, Captain.
Three to beam up.
Staring at it isn't going
to make it change shape.
It's blood, all right.
Not a trace
of changeling protoplasm
in your entire system.
Type "O" negative,
if you're wondering.
I'll be sure
to remember that.
Well, physiologically,
you're completely human.
Except for my face.
Yes, I was wondering
about that--
why they left it unchanged.
They left it this way
on purpose--
to make sure
I'd never forget what I was...
and...
what I've lost.
SISKO:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 49962.4.
After leaving
our Jem'Hadar escorts
at the edge of Dominion space
the Defiant has returned home.
But for Constable Odo,
I'm afraid
the journey has just begun.
How does it feel?
You comfortable?
Not too tight?
It's fine.
Though it does
make me feel a bit...
Itchy?
It's the Inkarian wool.
You'll get used to it.
Unless, of course, you're
allergic to Inkarian wool.
No, it's not
the uniform.
I...
I think I'm...
hungry?
You know, I envy you.
Well, think of all
the wonderful foods
you'll get to enjoy
for the first time.
Hmph! I can hardly wait.
Well, you've done your job.
Now I have to do mine.
Yes, I suppose you do.
Six months
in a holding cell, hmm?
The thought is unattractive,
to say the least.
Well, if you ask me, Captain
Sisko let you off lightly.
Sabotage, assaulting
a Federation officer,
attempting to incite war
between the Federation
and the Dominion.
Yes, but my heart
was in the right place.
Hmph.
AROYA:
There you are, Odo.
I've been looking
all over for you.
I heard about what happened.
I'm so sorry.
Oh...
thank you.
I know it won't be easy,
but eventually
you'll see how being a humanoid
has its advantages.
If there's anything at all
I can do, just let me know.
What a generous offer.
( sighs )
Let's go, Garak.
Constable?
You all right?
It's nothing.
It's just a headache.
Every once in a while, I
still get flashes of memory
from the Great Link--
a jumble of images,
or a word--
but I can't quite
make sense of it.
You know, there's
no reason to rush things.
You don't have to go back
to work right away.
Yes, I do!
When I joined
with the other changelings
in the Great Link, I...
felt something
I've never felt before.
In that moment...
I knew I was home.
For the first time
I felt that I
understood my people--
their distrust of the solids,
their willingness to do anything
to protect themselves.
And then...
in an instant,
it was all snatched away.
I'm trapped inside this body.
I can never rejoin
the Great Link.
My job is the only thing
I have left.
Besides, I'm still the best
law enforcement officer
on this station.
You're the best
law enforcement officer
in this sector--
maybe the whole damn Quadrant.
Maybe.
( raised voices )
What's that all about?
I have no idea.
The Klingon Empire
is tired of words
of negotiation,
of the endless delaying tactics
of the Federation.
Therefore, as of today,
a Klingon task force
has been dispatched
to the Archanis sector.
Starfleet has ten days
to abandon their bases
and withdraw their forces
from the sector.
It's coming in
on all frequencies.
...after that time
will be considered the enemy
and fired upon.
Major, put the station
on combat alert.
Notify the Bajoran militia.
Captain...
Those in the Klingon Empire...
It's him.
Gowron?
What about him?
During the Link
I sensed that the
other changelings
were trying to hide
things from me--
faces, names...
one of them was him.
What are you saying?
I'm saying
that he's one of them.
Gowron, the head
of the Klingon Empire,
is a changeling.
GOWRON:
Let there be no mistake,
no misinterpretation
of my words.
Archanis is ours
and we will take it back.
Resist us in any way
and there will be war.