Captain's Log,
Stardate 50049.3.
We're conducting a mineral
survey of Torga IV,
an uninhabited planet
in the Gamma Quadrant
believed to contain
vast deposits of cormaline.
Our mission is to
determine the feasibility
of establishing
a mining operation
on the planet's surface.
Hey, Muniz.
What do you think of this?
It's a class-5
pyroclastic debris and ash.
Same morphology we've seen
all the way up, sir.
How many times do
I have to tell you to
stop calling me "sir"?
I'm not an officer.
Well, you know
more than they do.
Well, I wouldn't go
that far. But I do
know more than you,
so listen to me while I try
and teach you something.
This morphology is
not exactly the same.
These deposits are
more highly eroded.
So?
So... they're
different, that's all.
Just thought I'd point
that out to you.
I see.
I thought maybe
you just stopped
to catch your breath.
Me, out of breath?
I was climbing
mountains in Ireland
before you were born.
You mean "hills,"
don't you?
They have gently sloping
hills in Ireland.
No mountains.
But what do I know?
After all, you're
the mountain man...
an old mountain man.
You know something, Muniz?
You're due for a transfer.
How does waste extraction sound?
How's it going, Chief?
Fine, sir.
We finished the survey
of the south slope.
What do you think, old man?
Is this place
worth mining?
Absolutely. The cormaline
is only a few hundred meters
below the surface, and if
my readings are correct,
it's one of the richest
veins I've ever seen.
Mr. Worf?
Strategically,
the planet's location
would make it difficult
to maintain
adequate supply lines,
but not impossible.
Hoya to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
Sir, our sensors have detected
a ship dropping out of warp.
What kind of ship?
I'm not sure, sir.
I can't get
a good reading on it.
Plasma leaks
from its warp nacelles
are disrupting our sensors.
Whatever it is, it's fallen
into the gravitational pull
of the planet.
It should enter the atmosphere
near your position.
Sir, the ship
withstood the impact.
Survivors?
I can't determine that.
We're having trouble penetrating
the hull with our sensors.
Beam us directly
to the crash site.
A warship.
A Jem'Hadar warship.
DAX:
No hull breach.
The only damage I could find
was a crushed guidance thruster
if that's what it is.
O'BRIEN:
Captain, I think we have
an access point.
I'll be right there.
So, my young friend
what do you think
we're looking at?
An upside-down ship.
( chuckling ):
An airlock?
A maintenance hatch?
Maybe.
But this is a warship.
On a warship, you want
a big access point
on the belly to...
land troops.
There's hope
for you yet, Muniz.
Can you open it, Chief?
I think so.
( mechanical clanking )
Mr. Worf, take the point.
T'Lor, you stay put.
( quietly ):
Commander, secure the area.
( creaking )
( gasps )
These men didn't die
in the crash.
They've been dead for hours.
What killed them?
Massive osteonecrosis.
Every bone in their
body's been shattered.
Sounds like
inertial damper failure.
The ship accelerated...
people were thrown
into the bulkheads.
Nobody was alive when
this ship hit the planet,
yet it survived the impact.
Whoever designed this baby
knew what they were doing.
No viewscreen, no chairs...
O'BRIEN:
No EPS conduits.
No microfusion initiators.
No power converters--
at least none
that I can find.
I suppose getting
this ship up and running
won't be easy.
I can't even determine
if it has a warp drive.
I wonder if this is what all
the Jem'Hadar ships are like.
The bigger question is:
What's a Jem'Hadar ship
doing all the way out here?
We're at least three weeks away
from the nearest
Dominion outpost.
Captain, there are
29 other bodies.
No survivors.
Can we use the runabout's
tractor beam to haul
this thing into orbit?
This would be the greatest
intelligence find
in the last ten years.
We're not going to leave
it here to rust.
What do you say, Chief?
Well, we're not
going to haul it out
with a runabout.
Then we need something
with a little more muscle.
BASHIR:
We'll let the Major
be the judge of that.
What I'm saying is,
if you're going
to prosecute me,
I demand that you prosecute
my coconspirator.
I'm not a conspirator.
What would you call
yourself, Doctor?
An idiot.
I'll buy that.
For asking your help
in the first place.
Would someone please tell
me what's going on here?
Quark brought aboard a shipment
of Regalian fleaspiders
without an import permit.
He asked for them!
The spiders were
for you, Major.
I can synthesize a drug
from their venom
which should improve
your circulation.
But I didn't know
I needed a permit
to import them.
So what's the problem?
Fill out the paperwork.
ODO:
It's not
that simple anymore.
It seems that Quark
took the opportunity
to import illegal
Regalian liquid crystals
along with the fleaspiders.
The crystals are
a highly intoxicating
and sometimes dangerous
aphrodisiac.
What's love
without danger?
I don't have time for this.
I just spoke with Captain Sisko.
They found a crashed Jem'Hadar
ship in the Gamma Quadrant.
They need
the Defiant right away.
I'll be back in about a week.
When do we leave?
I'm leaving right away.
I'd say you have some
legal problems to work out.
Gentlemen...
O'BRIEN:
It's embedded about 90
meters into the rock.
If I can shake it loose by
firing the main thrusters
hauling it out of here
will be a lot easier.
There's a problem?
Well, to fire
the main thrusters,
I need to calibrate
the plasma injectors.
So far, I can't get a
grip on the ion regulator.
You want to try a hyper-spanner
above the matrix?
It might open it up a bit.
Maybe we won't send you
to waste extraction
after all, Muniz.
WORF:
Captain...
we buried the bodies
on the other side
of that ridge.
The DNA readings--
42 Jem'Hadar, one Vorta.
Hoya to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
A Jem'Hadar warship
has just dropped out of warp.
Break orbit
and get out of sight.
They've locked phasers on us.
Hard to port!
Shields are down!
Engage warp!
( screams )
Inside! We don't stand
a chance in the open.
We may not be safe in here.
The Jem'Hadar can transport
through just about anything.
( footsteps )
Why do they not come?
Give them time.
Watch our backs,
Commander.
We're moving to
the Command Center.
Can you walk?
Faster than you can.
Let me take a look at this.
I'm all right, Captain.
I've had worse
transporter burns.
Where's the medkit?
DAX:
T'Lor had it.
I don't need it, sir.
I'll be all right.
We have to stop
the bleeding.
I'll take care of that.
( groans )
Transporter burn.
"I'm all right, Captain."
Always kissing up
to the officers
aren't you, Muniz?
Just following your example.
You're my hero.
( cloth rips )
Hey!
I have to get to the wound.
But this is
my best uniform.
It's the only one
that fits right.
Don't worry.
When we get back,
we'll have Garak
make you a new one.
How long till
the Defiant
gets here?
Two and a half days.
Don't worry, Jefe.
I'll get you through this.
I feel better already.
We've only got one
portable generator.
The rest are at base camp.
Looks like you need
a new bandage, Enrique.
( equipment powering up )
Ah. Thanks, Chief.
I'll take it
from here, Commander.
Quique, do me a favor.
Please...
stop bleeding before
I run out of clothes.
I'll do the best I can.
What do you make
of this, old man?
My guess, it's some kind
of virtual sensory display.
The Jem'Hadar equivalent
of our viewscreen?
There are only
two headsets.
One for the Vorta and one
for the Jem'Hadar First.
Guess they're the only ones
who get to see what's
going on outside.
Captain Sisko,
my name is Kilana.
I'm the Vorta in charge
of the Jem'Hadar troops
surrounding you.
If you touch
the triangular green panel
on any of
the control consoles,
you'll be able to speak to me.
They know your name.
They always seem to be
one step ahead of us.
( beeps )
This is Captain Sisko.
Captain, I'm so happy
to hear your voice.
I heard there were
some casualties among your crew
and I feared
you may have been one of them.
Thank you for your concern.
What do you want?
To talk. I think it would be
in everyone's best interest
if you and I met face-to-face
and discussed the situation,
like reasonable people.
I can be reasonable.
So I've heard.
One escort each.
Agreed?
Agreed.
Your photograph
doesn't do you justice.
You're quite
striking in person.
Uh, look, I'm a little busy,
so let's skip the flattery.
Weyoun's report
on you was right.
You are direct.
I like that.
So, let me cut
to the chase.
I believe that is
the correct expression.
This is our ship.
We want it back.
Was your ship.
Now it's mine.
Oh.
Captain, I'm...
I'm a little disappointed.
That's the attitude of a thief,
not a Starfleet Captain
with a reputation for integrity.
This is clearly our property.
What gives you any claim to it?
An old legal tradition--
salvage rights.
We found a wrecked ship
and a dead crew,
and we found it first.
A very
interesting
position.
But I'm afraid the Dominion
doesn't recognize that...
tradition.
What may be
even more to the point,
we have you completely
surrounded and outnumbered.
Would you like
something to eat, Captain?
Or maybe something to drink?
These are q'lavas--
a personal favorite.
They're not poisonous, if
that's what you're thinking.
Not to you, anyway.
I hope you're not
teaching Jake to be
this suspicious, Benjamin.
Or do you prefer Ben?
"Captain" will be fine.
I'm sure it's my fault
that we seem unable
to establish an understanding
between us, Captain.
I'm sorry I'm not more
experienced in these matters.
This is my first mission
outside the Dominion
and my very first dealing
with anyone from the Federation.
I know you have
no reason to trust me,
but I hope you'll at least try
to consider my offer
with an open mind.
I'm listening.
If you'll leave
our ship,
I'll take you and your crew
back to your space station--
unharmed.
Our accommodations
may not be lavish,
but I promise
you'll all be well cared for
especially your wounded.
If you think I'm going
to deliver my people
into your hands
without a fight,
then this really must be
your first mission.
( moans )
( beeping )
I'd love to know how
the Captain's doing.
Any chance you can get
this thing working?
Not right away.
I'm still trying to get
the main power grid on line.
( clicking, soft thumps )
What's that?
( soft ticking )
That wasn't there before.
You sure?
Positive.
It's some kind
of sensor device.
Whatever it is, it doesn't
look too friendly.
Captain.
They're in the ship.
I knew it.
You've been goldbricking
all along.
Like I said,
you taught me everything I know.
Whatever this sensor
was supposed to do,
it did it and
then shut down.
Probably
a surveillance device.
To find out how many
of us there are...
how many weapons
we have.
( Muniz groans )
I don't think so.
They seem
to know all that already.
But it doesn't make sense.
If he had a rifle,
O'Brien and I would be dead,
but all he had was a knife.
And why send only
one Jem'Hadar?
( sighs ):
There's something
about this ship,
something so important that
they won't risk destroying it
in a full-on assault.
If that is true,
then we must find
out what it is.
Captain, the first thing
we need to do
is make a structural scan
of the ship.
Make our own blueprints.
Get started.
( groaning )
I'm leaking like a ruptured
plasma conduit, aren't I, sir?
It's not that bad.
You're lying.
What makes you say that?
I called you "sir"
and you didn't even flinch.
I must be dying.
Now you listen
to me, Quique.
You're not dying unless
I say you're dying,
and I say you're
going to make it.
How are you doing, Muniz?
We seem to be having
a difference of opinion
on that one, sir.
But I would like
to file a complaint.
The nurses around here
are all thumbs.
You watch it,
or I'll tighten this bandage
like a tourniquet.
And as for bedside manner,
I've known nicer voles.
Certainly prettier ones.
You keep moving around,
you won't need any nurse.
Listen to the
Chief, Muniz.
Save your strength.
I'm worried about
him, Captain.
I can't stop
the bleeding.
Maybe it's a side effect
of the Jem'Hadar weapons.
They must leave some kind
of anticoagulant.
If I don't get him to
a medical bay soon, he's
not going to make it.
None of us are going
to make it if we don't
get this ship operational.
I need to get
the power grid functioning
and the aft
turret weapon on line.
You're the only one
who can do that.
I'll take care of Muniz.
Captain--
You have your orders.
Yes, sir.
( sighs )
Chief...
structurally,
a lot about this ship's design
matches the other
Jem'Hadar warships we've seen.
But there are
significant differences.
There are many systems
that we are completely
unfamiliar with.
I can start to restore
power to the systems
one at a time.
That'll give us a
chance to test them
and establish
their functions,
but it's going
to take awhile.
How long?
I wish I knew.
Well, you can do it, Chief.
I don't think
a ship's been invented
that you can't figure out.
Muniz is strong.
He'll make it.
No. He will not.
He will not see tomorrow.
You keep that
to yourself.
I don't want him to
hear that kind of talk.
It does no good
to shield him from the truth.
Let him prepare for death.
The hell I will.
His only hope is
to keep fighting.
If he gives up, it's over.
It was over the moment
he was shot by the Jem'Hadar.
Now, you listen to me.
That boy's life
is in our hands,
and I won't let anybody
give up on him.
Worf, what do you say
we go look
at that ion exchange matrix
we found?
And on the way,
maybe we can discuss
some of the finer points
of diplomacy.
KILANA:
Captain Sisko.
Captain, you're annoyed with me.
I understand.
You feel betrayed,
and with good reason
but I really think
we should talk.
If it will make you feel
any better,
I'll come unarmed
and without an escort,
but I won't hold you
to the same restrictions.
If you have something
to say, say it.
Sending the Jem'Hadar
into the ship was a mistake,
and I apologize.
I trust no one was hurt,
but what choice did I have?
Just like you have to protect
the lives of your men,
I have to protect our...
property.
But I do hope
we can put that behind us
and move on.
Move on to what?
I'm sure it's obvious by now
there's something
in the ship we want.
You allow me and my men
to retrieve the item,
we'll leave.
You can keep the ship.
How about this?
You tell me what it is you want
and I'll bring it out to you.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
Don't you trust me?
I'd like to, Captain,
but I can't.
Not under these circumstances.
There's simply...
too much at stake for us.
We've got a lot at stake, too.
I won't risk
the lives of my crew.
Well, it seems
we're approaching an impasse.
We've already arrived.
How unfortunate.
The negotiations have ended.
( loud, whooshing thud )
( rumbling thud )
( thuds continue )
( whooshing thuds continue )
I take it things
could have gone better.
( beeping )
All the ship's systems
are shutting down, Captain.
( groaning )
I need to know what's
going on out there.
Chief, get me some
sensor readings.
Dax, take care
of Muniz.
( gasping )
I can't feel my legs.
Don't worry,
they're there.
I managed to bypass
the virtual display interface
and hook up a tricorder
to the ship's sensor array.
Those are ultritium concussion
shells they're detonating.
Without shields, a direct
hit would destroy us.
I do not believe
they are trying
to hit us.
Their targeting
systems cannot be
that ineffective.
They're trying
to rattle us.
( explosion )
And we're not going
to let them do that.
The Vorta doesn't want the ship.
She wants something aboard it.
Any idea what?
It could be anything...
encoding device,
guidance system...
Maybe she lost an earring.
Whatever it is,
it's keeping us alive.
Find it!
Chief...
I need that weapon.
I'll still have to charge
the emitter arrays.
Stay on it.
( thudding explosions
continue)
You have your weapon, sir.
Nice work,
Mr. O'Brien.
But the bad news is...
the turret is stuck.
You can only fire
in one direction.
Maybe we'll get lucky
and the Jem'Hadar
will pick that place
to stand.
( explosion )
( Muniz groaning )
Easy, Quique.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
I'm not afraid, Papa.
It's beautiful.
Precioso.
( explosion )
Better than last year,
don't you think?
Los cohetes...
the fireworks
of the carnival...
they're terrific,
aren't they?
Easy, Quique.
( explosion )
The colors...
like a thousand shooting stars.
( explosion )
That was a good one, huh?
Yeah, that was
a good one.
I'll say one thing
for the Jem'Hadar.
They travel light.
No cargo, no storage
compartments.
I did find
these data crystals
in one of the
computer rooms.
There may be some encoded
information on them,
but the crystal structure
has been randomized.
In other words,
they're blank.
As far as
I can tell.
It would help
if we knew what
we were looking for.
( explosion )
But we don't.
( Muniz speaking Spanish )
Las estrellas...
mira... que bonita.
En la noche, bonita...
Commander.
What is it?
It may have been
the Vorta's computer console.
I found it in one of
the upper compartments,
but the power grid is off-line
in that part of the ship.
So you ripped it
out of the wall.
Very nice.
So, what do we
do with it now?
Use it for a doorstop?
I do not care
what you do with it.
Worf, I was kidding.
It was a good idea.
We'll hook it up and see
if we can get it working.
( explosion )
You'd think
they'd be tired
of playing this game
with us by now.
I have a game I would
like to play with them.
If only I could
leave this prison
and meet them face-to-face
on a field of battle.
Right now, that doesn't
sound like a bad idea.
Chief, could you
take a look
at that console?
( explosions continue )
That is no way
for anyone to die.
I told you,
he is not going to die.
It is only
a matter of time.
So we should
just kill him, right?
If you truly are his friend,
you would consider that option.
It would be
a more honorable death
than the one
he's enduring.
I'm not some
blood-thirsty Klingon
looking for an excuse
to murder my friend.
That's enough.
No.
You are just
another weak human
afraid to face death.
( yells )
I said that's enough!
You're Starfleet officers.
Now, start acting like it!
Tough guys--
a little pressure
and they buckle.
Dax, maybe you haven't noticed,
but no one's laughing.
Now, I know it's hot.
We're filthy. Tired.
And we've got ten isotons
of explosives going off outside.
But we will never
get out of this if we don't
pull it together
and start to act
like professionals.
( shuddering groan )
( explosion )
Chief, I want that power grid
up and running.
Aye, sir.
Commander Worf, see if you
can get that turret to rotate.
Aye, sir.
( explosion )
Dax, search the ship
again and again
until you find
what the Vorta wants.
Yes, sir.
( explosion )
( sighs )
And you, Mr. Muniz...
your orders are...
to stay alive.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
The Jem'Hadar barrage
has continued on and off
for ten hours.
Chief O'Brien has restored
main power and helm control.
If we can bring
the ship's engines on line,
we may be able to lift off
and escape from here.
As soon as we finish calibrating
the induction reactors,
we can fire up the main core.
( explosion )
Good, because, unless
there are any objections,
I'd like to get
the hell off this planet.
I'm for that.
Ready, Chief.
I could use
a couple more hours
to fine-tune
the magnetic flux couplers,
but under the circumstances,
now's as good a time as any.
Then let's do it.
Everyone brace yourselves.
This is going to be
a rough ride.
Commence
launch sequence.
Ion thrusters
fully charged.
Ventral impellers,
one quarter.
Plasma compensators,
on line.
Thrusters to one half.
Chief, I'm getting
a low-frequency resonance
in the main reactor housing.
That's all right.
Just keep compensating
with the inertial dampers.
Dampers are at maximum.
We need more power.
Ventral jets to one half.
It's working, Captain.
These engines
just might shake us loose.
Increase power to one half.
Main reactor housing,
destabilizing.
Reactor containment field
overloading.
Induction dampers
disintegrating, Captain.
If we don't cut power, we're
going to have a core breach.
Disengage thrusters.
Power down all systems.
( explosion )
How bad?
Main power grid
is completely fused.
Structural integrity field
has collapsed.
We'll have to wait until
the Defiant gets here.
She'll be able to
pull us out of here
with a tractor beam.
Which means we have 36 hours
to make repairs.
You all know what to do.
I could really
use your help now, Quique.
( explosion )
I told Muniz
he was going to make it.
That's what a Captain's
supposed to say.
( explosion )
I have got to get this ship
back to the station, old man.
Five people have died
on this mission.
I want to be able
to tell their families why.
( explosion )
Ben...
It's a changeling.
( squealing roar )
It can't hold
its shape.
It's dying.
Then we're in trouble.
That's what the Vorta
has been looking for--
a Founder.
No wonder the Jem'Hadar
wouldn't attack.
They couldn't risk
killing one of
their gods.
( changeling shrieks )
( distant shrieking
continues)
The bombing stopped.
Prepare for an assault.
Tell Worf to man the--
Where are your soldiers?
They're dead.
They killed themselves.
Why?
Because they allowed
a Founder to die.
You should have trusted me.
How could I?!
The first word out of
your mouth was a lie!
This isn't your
first mission outside
the Dominion, is it?
I regret saying that,
but my offer was genuine.
All that mattered to me
was the Founder.
Then you should have
told me about him.
You might have killed him
or made him a hostage.
No.
All I wanted was the ship.
And I was willing
to let you take it.
So...
this is how it ends.
( footsteps approaching )
It's true.
The Jem'Hadar died
by their own hands.
Muniz...
the runabout crew...
your soldiers...
they'd all still be alive
if we had trusted each other.
I have no way of stopping you
from taking the ship.
All I ask is that you
allow me to remove
some of the Founder's remains.
Of course.
Do you have any gods,
Captain Sisko?
There are things I believe in.
Duty?
Starfleet? The Federation?
You must be pleased
with yourself.
You have this ship
to take back to them.
I hope it was worth it.
So do I.
( sighing )
What did Starfleet
have to say about
our prize?
They're pleased.
That's all?
Just pleased?
Very pleased.
They're giving us all medals.
I'll add it
to my collection.
Starfleet Command is waiting
for my official report,
but every time I try
to get it started...
I find myself staring
at the casualty list
and reading
the same five names
over and over again.
T'Lor, Rooney,
Bertram, Hoya, Muniz.
It may sound cruel,
but we both know
that ship out there
was worth it.
Those five deaths
may save 5,000 lives,
or maybe even five million.
And if I had to make the same
trade all over again, I would.
But five people are dead.
Fine men and women who deserved
a lot more than to die
on some lonely planet
50,000 light-years
away from home!
( bangs padd )
When you were
at the Academy,
was Professor Somak teaching?
Moral and Ethical Issues
of Command.
I remember her favorite speech:
"Always maintain
emotional distance
between yourself
and those under your command."
It's good advice.
And I try to follow it,
but it's a lot more complicated
outside of the classroom.
Did you know
that Jake and Muniz
have the same birthday?
That I performed
the ceremony at Hoya's wedding?
And Rooney--
he could play the trumpet.
I heard him
at Quark's once,
and he had the people
dancing in the aisles.
I remember.
And you know something else
I remember about him?
How proud he was
to wear his uniform
and how proud he was
to serve under you.
The same as Hoya,
T'Lor, Bertram and Muniz.
They chose a life
in Starfleet.
They knew the risks,
and they died
fighting for something
that they believed in.
That doesn't make it any easier.
Maybe nothing should.
We used a phase-conjugate
graviton emitter
in the tractor beam.
That baby came out
of the rock first time.
You would have
loved it, Quique.
( door opens )
I did not mean to interrupt.
It's all right.
You are performing
Ak'voh
for your friend.
I am?
Yes. It's an old
Klingon tradition.
When a warrior dies in battle,
his comrades stay with the body
to keep away predators.
That allows the spirit
to leave the body
when it is time to make
the long journey
to Sto'Vo'Kor.
It's a fine tradition.
What are you doing?
We will both keep
the predators away.
I'm sure Quique
would like that.