I knew that my paper
was controversial,
but I had no idea
that it would turn
the entire conference
upside-down.
Believe me, Jake,
panel discussions
between doctors
are usually a lot more
civilized than that.
I don't know.
They seemed
polite enough to me.
Oh, that was just a veneer.
That paper stepped
on quite a few toes,
I can tell you.
It's heresy
to even consider the possibility
that a prion replication
could be inhibited
by quantum resonance effects.
Aren't you going
to take any notes?
Oh, good idea.
According to the
so-called experts
it's all a matter
of amino acid re-sequencing
and disulfide shuffling.
Quantum dynamics has nothing
to do with it.
But how can that be?
( thinking ):
I have absolutely no idea
what he's talking about.
...on a quantum level.
Ah, get this.
This is very good.
A few months ago...
If I don't find a way to get
out of doing this article,
my first writing assignment
is going to be my last.
Maybe if I write to the Journal
and explain.
"Dear Editors, thank you
"for the confidence
you expressed in me
"by accepting my proposed
profile of Dr. Bashir.
Unfortunately..."
Do you follow?
Sort of.
Good, because that's the key.
The protein anomalies--
Who cares about anomalies?
People want stories about
things they can relate to:
Life and death, good and evil.
An outbreak
of Cartalian fever
would be just the thing.
"The brave doctor
battles the deadly virus."
Listen to me-- I'm actually
rooting for a plague.
...quantum-scanning
each and every peptide bond,
I thought I'd begin
to make some kind of...
( console beeps )
It's a distress call
from the Federation colony
on Ajilon Prime.
They're under attack.
The Klingons
have landed troops.
So much for
the cease fire.
The main hospital's
been damaged.
They're short on doctors
and running low on supplies.
What are we waiting
for? Let's go.
It's too risky.
The hospital's only
50 kilometers away
from the front line.
You put yourself into
dangerous situations
all the time.
Maybe, but that's not the same
as putting you into one.
Don't worry about me.
You're too young
to die, Jake.
I'm 18.
You know
what I mean.
I've been on the station
when it was under attack
plenty of times.
I can handle myself.
I'm a Sisko.
There are lives at stake.
These people need you.
( sighs ):
I hope I don't
regret this.
We'll be there
in just under an hour.
I can only imagine what
your father's going to say.
He'll understand.
I'll get you out of there
as soon
as reinforcements arrive.
Besides,
I wouldn't want you
to miss the deadline
on your story.
Do you think they'd want
a picture of me?
( chuckling )
Anyway, about those
quantum scans
I was telling you about...
"Surgery under Fire."
( chuckles to himself )
Now we're talking.
What is it, Quark?
The Chief asked me
to come up
with a decaffeinated
raktajino for Kira.
I'm thinking
of marketing it.
Ugh! Ugh!
Oh, that's awful.
Give it a chance.
( laughs dryly )
Let me taste it.
Quark.
I did the best I could.
The removal of caffeine
from beverages
has plagued bartenders and
restaurateurs for centuries.
You can't expect me
to solve it overnight.
Well, I'm not
paying for that.
So much
for "Quark-tajino."
O'BRIEN:
I wanted to get her
off caffeine,
not poison her.
You make me sound
like some kind of addict.
She has maybe two
raktajinos a day.
Look, I just don't
want my son to be born
with a caffeine
habit, that's all.
You're being
ridiculous.
Why does pregnancy
always make men
hysterical?
Excuse me. This is not
the first baby I've had.
Excuse me.
Keiko had Molly.
It's not up to you
to tell Kira
what she can
and cannot do.
She is carrying
his child.
He should have
some say.
As the lessee, he does
have certain rights.
Back home, pregnancy
is considered a rental.
Rental?
( door opens )
( sighs )
Something wrong,
Captain?
I just talked to Dr. Bashir.
He's on his way to Ajilon Prime
to answer a request
for medical assistance.
Jake's with him.
According to the
latest reports,
Klingon ground troops
have captured two settlements
in the northern
hemisphere.
Half the colonists
are still trapped
on the planet,
and there are no ships
in the area to evacuate them.
We're three days
away at best.
The Farragut will get there
the day after tomorrow.
Bashir says that he and Jake
will leave
as soon as the relief teams
are in place.
That means they'll
be home by Thursday.
Doesn't give
you much time
to snoop through
Jake's things.
Ready to beam down?
No, we can't leave
the runabout in orbit.
Not with the Klingons around.
Besides, the colonists
moved what was left
of the medical equipment
underground
when the hospital
was destroyed.
And there's magnesite
in the rock face.
There's no way
to transport through it.
I guess we'll have to
find a place to set down.
Looks like
there's a clearing
about a kilometer away
from the main settlement.
Jake... things could get
a little rough down there.
They've got a lot
of wounded.
I'll be all right.
We've got more wounded
coming in!
WOMAN:
I need that plasma!
WOMAN 2:
Are you Bashir?
We got a distress call.
Resource said
you were on your way.
Watch it. Watch it!
This is the last IP.
His pulse is thready.
He must be
bleeding somewhere.
We are losing him!
Dr. Kalandra!
Bashir, drop in,
standard triage.
Give him
15 milligrams
inaprovaline.
What should I do?
Just keep out
of the way, please.
Get this man
into surgery!
The artery's severed.
Her BP's
bottoming out!
NURSE:
O2, three liters.
One full saline.
Somebody, this man
needs some help!
Help me!
Somebody, help me!
I've been hit.
Took a disruptor
blast, real close.
I need that blood plasma!
Let's get you
up on the table.
There's nothing we can do.
He's too far gone.
( groaning )
It doesn't look
that bad.
I was stepping
over a Klingon.
I thought
he was dead.
He caught me right
in the foot... ah!
You people better
get out of here
while you still can.
The Klingons...
there's no stopping them.
This is a phaser burn.
What are you talking about?!
Just sit tight.
We'll... get to you
as soon as we can.
It's not a phaser burn!
It was a Klingon.
You weren't there.
You don't know
what it's like.
The Klingons had us pinned down.
We were done for.
We all knew it.
Hendriks and Pajal,
they got scared. They ran.
They ran.
Then Sully got hit in the leg...
and the medics
pulled him off the line
and all I could think was...
"I wish I were him."
And I took my phaser...
( sobbing )
Oh, God!
What did I do
to myself?
What did I do?
Find someplace else
to stand.
No problem.
"Triage--
the sorting of the wounded--
forces decisions that..."
I got to get a grip... focus.
"...decisions that test
what it means to be a doctor."
MAN:
Hey, you!
Give me a hand.
Come on! Come on!
I've got to get some plasma
for this guy.
Keep an eye on him for me.
I'll be right back.
Wait, wait, wait.
This way.
Over there.
Watch it.
Watch it!
Nice catch.
Here you are, sir, a nice
private room with a view.
One, two, three.
( grunting )
Well, you can count.
You're hired.
Let's get you dressed.
I'd like to try
an aortal graft.
All right, there's an extra
surgical table in the back.
He's dead.
( sighing )
Come on.
Let's get him out of here.
One, two, three...
( groaning )
( sighing )
Party's over.
So soon?
DOCTOR:
And we were
just starting
to have fun.
Since you two aren't busy,
would you mind carrying me
to the nearest replicator
so that I can get
something to eat?
You wanted to see me,
Captain?
Yes. I, uh,
hear you, uh...
took a little trip
to the Infirmary.
( snorts )
I'll be fine.
The only permanent damage
was to my pride.
What happened?
Quark wanted me
to keep an eye
on two Yridians
who he suspected
were cheating at dabo.
Turns out he was right.
I could see
from the second level
that one of them was using
a miniature
gravimetric scanner
to predict where the ball
would land on the wheel
and signaling the information
to his partner.
Ingenious. Go on.
Well, I started
down the stairs
to make the arrest.
One of them spotted me.
They bolted.
I pursued.
I'm afraid
I got a bit carried away...
And jumped off the stairs.
( grunts )
I was planning
to change form in midair
and become a Tarkalean condor.
Ah... that
would have been impressive.
I thought so.
It's an understandable mistake.
You've been a changeling
longer than you've been a solid.
( snorts )
Solid-- I wonder why my people
use that term.
Humanoid bodies are so fragile.
Yes, they are.
And there are a lot of ways
you can get hurt.
You're worried about Jake.
I'm... sure
that Dr. Bashir
is looking after him.
It seems... just yesterday
he was five years old...
clinging to me, because he'd
just scraped his knee,
and I was
the only one in the world
who could make it better.
I remember,
sometimes
getting up in the
middle of the night
and slipping into his room,
just to make sure
he was all right...
and I'd sit there
and watch him sleep
and I'd think to myself
that no matter what,
I wasn't going to let anything
bad happen to this child.
Now he's a sector away
in a war zone,
and there's nothing
I can do to protect him.
Try not to worry, Captain.
It won't do
you or Jake any good.
Can't help it.
It comes with the territory.
But Jake is 18 years old.
Does your father
still worry about you?
Oh, all the time.
Ah... I never realized
how stressful it is
to be a parent.
I have to say,
I don't think it's for me.
That's your choice, but you
don't know what you're missing.
( door chimes )
Yes?
We just got word-- the
Klingons have destroyed
the Farragut near
the Lembatta cluster.
What about Ajilon Prime?
Without reinforcements--
Dax, you're with me.
We'll leave as soon
as the Defiant is ready.
Here you go.
Thanks.
How you holding up?
Okay.
Well, you handled
yourself well today.
I'm impressed.
I'm starved.
Think I'll start by making
a lateral incision
across the thigh joint.
Uh-oh.
Hang on.
Out we go.
His first day?
Yeah.
Pass the salt.
How do you feel?
Fresh air did me good.
You remember that ensign,
the one who shot himself?
How could I forget?
What's going
to happen to him?
Oh, he'll probably be
court-martialed.
He said that some
of the people in his squad
got scared and ran.
It happens.
But they're Starfleet.
They've passed psych tests.
They've spent hundreds of hours
in battle simulations.
Simulations can't prepare you
for the real thing.
Nothing can.
Some people say
that you don't know
what you're really made of
until you've been in battle.
Well, let me tell you, Jake.
There are many
situations in life
which test a person's
character.
Thankfully, most of them
don't involve
death and destruction.
Dr. Kalandra is looking for you.
Something about
that aortal graft you did.
Oh, thanks.
Um... I'll see you later.
I put your tray
back in the replicator.
I didn't know
how long you'd be gone.
Me neither.
I think I could
handle some soup.
How is he?
The graft's holding.
Blood throughput
is almost 100 percent.
Nice job.
Thanks.
You have a good team.
My O.R. nurse was
as sharp as they come.
We do the best we
can, considering...
the circumstances.
So, are things
any better for us?
Last I heard,
Starfleet had pulled out
of the Archanis sector.
Well, the fleet's regrouping
for a counterattack.
Do you have any idea
what ships are involved?
We don't get much news here.
The Klingons have been jamming
the subspace traffic.
I think, um, the Rutledge
and the Tecumseh
are heading
things up.
The Tecumseh.
My husband's
the science officer.
Well, believe me,
Captain Raymond
is one of the best there is.
He saw the Tecumseh
through the Cardassian wars.
I don't think he's planning
on losing her now.
No.
I don't suppose he is.
Doctor?
They've prepped
the spinal trauma.
We're ready for
you in surgery.
I'll be right there.
They're keeping
you busy.
Yes.
It helps keep
my mind... off things.
It's good to see
you got your appetite back.
I have a pretty
strong stomach...
most of the time.
Don't worry about it.
Same thing happened
to me my first day.
You know what I heard?
That ship Starfleet
sent--- the Farragut--
the Klingons
intercepted it.
Starfleet will send
another one, won't they?
Won't be
here for days,
and in the meantime,
we're looking at a ground war,
which is just
what the Klingons want,
and according
to a lieutenant I talked to,
they've got so many
transport scramblers on line
that we can't beam
troops anywhere.
What about using hoppers?
He says the Klingons
have been shooting them
out of the sky left and right.
Unless something changes,
he figures the Klingons
will take the settlement
the day after tomorrow.
Did you see
all the bat'leth wounds today?
Klingons get mad,
they forget about their
disruptors, go hand to hand.
If you ask me,
they're looking to get even
for what happened on Ganalda IV.
What happened?
They had to retreat.
Klingons hate that.
( sighing )
At least we don't have to worry
about them in here.
Oh, don't
be so sure.
Medical personnel
are fair game,
as far as Klingons
are concerned.
They'll even kill wounded
right in their beds.
Think they're giving
them an honorable death.
So, how'd you wind up here?
I, uh... I'm writing
an article about Dr. Bashir.
You're a journalist?
No, not exactly.
What does that mean?
I write stories, mostly--
you know, fiction.
( thinking ):
I wonder if Kirby knew
that the whole time
we were talking,
all I could think about was
how close the Klingons were.
He didn't seem that worried.
No one else seems
to be losing sleep over it,
so why is it the only thing
I can think about?
I've been on the station
when it was under attack
plenty of times,
but somehow the danger
never seemed as real
as it does here.
Maybe it's
because I spent all day
seeing first-hand what
the Klingons are capable of,
or maybe it's because,
for the first time in my life,
my father's not here
to protect me.
( explosion )
What was that?
The Klingons.
They must have taken out
the reactor.
( people calling out orders )
Come on, come on!
( gasping )
She's fibrillating.
If we don't get power back soon,
we'll lose half the ward.
KIRBY:
Kidney failure, he's
going into renal shock.
I just talked to Resource.
It's going to be
at least three hours
before we have power.
( sighs )
There must be some portable
generators we could use.
They're using them
to keep the shields up
around the settlement.
The runabout.
There's a portable
generator on the runabout.
Where is it?
About a kilometer
south of here.
I'll need help
carrying it though.
Well, you won't be able
to beam through the shields.
You'll have to take
the east tunnel.
That lets out
beyond the perimeter.
I'll show you.
We set down
just over that ridge.
Yeah. It looks familiar.
Get down!
Stay close.
And keep
your head low.
Whatever happens, one of us
has to get that generator.
Stick with me.
Come on, Jake!
Jake!
( grunts )
( explosions continue )
( panting )
( yells )
( groaning )
Medkit...
over there.
Now!
Hypo.
Sit me up.
( groaning )
Do it!
I'm not going to die
with my face in the dirt.
Okay...
How's your head?
Hurts.
You're lucky
I didn't kill you.
I thought you were
a Klingon.
Have you seen any?
What?
Klingons!
Are there any
patrols around?
What about Starfleet?
No.
It's just you and me then.
What are you doing
out here anyway?
Why'd you leave
the settlement?
I, uh... I was outside
when the shelling started.
I... I guess I got lost
looking for cover.
Lucky me.
I could use the company.
Here... water.
What about you?
Go ahead.
Thanks.
Probably would have
leaked out of me anyway.
Don't let me fall over.
I want to go out
looking up at the sky,
not at the ground.
Don't worry.
You didn't see a crashed
hopper around here,
did you?
No.
They made it.
Who?
My platoon.
The Klingons
had us pinned down.
We couldn't beam out
'cause they had
a transport scrambler running.
We called for a hopper.
As soon as it set down,
the Klingons came after us.
CO ordered me and Brice
to lay down cover
so the squad
could get up the ramp.
By the time
Brice got in,
the Klingons were
practically on top of us.
Hopper was taking
such a pounding,
I didn't think
it'd make it off the ground.
You stayed behind on purpose
so they could get away.
The hypo... where is it?
It's empty.
Figures.
I'll get you out of here.
I'll make a stretcher.
With what?
Then I'll carry you.
Kid, you try carrying
me, my guts
are going to spill
all over your shoes.
But I have to do something.
I've got to try.
Forget it.
But I have to.
That way,
this will all make sense.
Maybe I ran for a reason--
so I could find you and...
and save your life.
Ran?
From the explosions.
We had to get to the runabout,
for the generator.
And... the shelling started,
and I couldn't see Dr. Bashir,
and the explosions,
they kept getting closer.
I had to get out of there.
So I ran.
I ran and I kept running
until I found you.
The doctor-- you left him.
It was a mistake.
That's what you call it.
I didn't mean for it to happen.
And now you think
bringing me back
is going to make
everything all right.
( coughing )
Sorry, kid...
life doesn't work like that.
( choking )
Benjamin.
I'll be right out.
What have you been
doing in there
for three hours?
I was tweaking
the pattern buffers
in the replicator systems.
Great.
I always thought the coffee
could be a little hotter.
I'm just trying
to keep busy.
Is it helping?
No, not really.
I wish there was
something I could do.
Some way I could
promise you
that everything is
going to be okay.
But you can't.
No one can.
I know what it's like
to worry about a child.
Raifi put Tobin
through hell.
When Neema was six,
she came down
with Rugalan fever.
Audrid spent two weeks
in the hospital with her
and never left her side.
It was hundreds of years ago,
and I can still remember how...
helpless I felt.
I read her
all 17 volumes
of Caster's
Down the River Light,
even though I knew
she couldn't hear me.
It made me feel
like I was doing something--
that we were still connected.
It wasn't...
until much...
much after that,
that I realized that I
was doing it as much for me
as I was doing it for her.
Just to keep busy.
So, how did it turn out
with Neema?
She pulled through.
Whew. I was hoping you
were going to say that.
Because if this story
had an unhappy ending,
I would have never
forgiven you.
( chuckling )
Of course, by the
time she was 21,
she wouldn't
even speak to me.
For how long?
About eight years.
Do me a favor.
Tell me about it
some other time.
Right now, all I care about
is seeing Jake.
You will, tomorrow,
when we get to Ajilon Prime.
You know, Ben,
coffee can never be too hot.
Are you sure
you got
the replicator buffers
synchronized?
You want to check it
for yourself?
I think I will.
Can I borrow
your decoupler?
Get your own.
I have to check
the sonic shower relays.
Good idea.
How are you feeling?
Jake!
Jake, we thought
you were--
I'm okay.
This is great.
What happened?
I got knocked out when we tried
to get to the runabout.
Did Dr. Bashir
make it back all right?
He's in IC for the night.
He's got plasma burns
on his arm and shoulder.
I don't know
how he managed,
but he carried the generator
back here by himself.
We went looking for you right
after the shelling stopped.
I mean, there was
hardly anything left
of the runabout.
The whole place was nothing
but bomb craters and-and smoke.
We had pretty much
given up hope.
I must have wandered off in the
wrong direction when I came to.
You are lucky you didn't
get picked up by the Klingons.
Word is, they're massing
to attack the compound.
You want to see him?
No, I should let him rest.
He's awake.
I was just in there.
Go ahead.
He'll be glad
to see you're okay.
Jake?!
Oh!
Thank God!
I thought
you'd been killed.
Once the shelling
had stopped
and I couldn't
find you,
I assumed the worst.
I am so sorry.
It's all right.
No...
no, it isn't.
I should never have brought
you here in the first place.
Now we're stuck here, the
Klingons massing to attack...
What was I thinking?!
Forget it, okay!
What's done is...
is done.
I couldn't stand hearing him
apologize to me like that,
not after what I'd done to him.
All right, you two.
Visiting hours are over.
Let me have
a look at that.
I keep turning it over
in my head--
the shelling, losing sight
of Bashir, running--
and I keep trying
to make sense of it all,
to justify what I did.
But when it comes down to it,
there's only one explanation.
I'm a coward.
Part of me wishes Bashir
had seen me run away
and told everyone the truth.
They deserve
to know what I am.
They should know
they can't count on me.
That, if the Klingons attack,
I'll run and hide,
just like I did before.
Dr. Kalandra asked me
to give this to you.
Oh, thanks, Jake.
Would you take this
to the patient in G-4?
Sure.
Thanks.
Here you go.
Maybe I'll get
a job as a cutter.
Could be interesting work.
What's a cutter?
You know,
on a mining team.
They're the ones who split
asteroids up with phasers
so the excavators can
get at what's inside.
You got to have good aim,
and no matter what else
you can say about me,
you can't say that I
don't have good aim.
Because if I hadn't
hit my foot just right,
I would have taken
my whole leg off.
It's funny.
One minute, your
life's moving along
just like you always
thought it would,
and the next,
you do something
that changes everything,
and that makes you realize
you're not who you
thought you were.
At the Academy,
I did really well
in the battle
simulations.
I never had
any problems.
But when you're out there,
and the live shells
are detonating
all around you,
it's a whole
different thing.
All you can think about
is getting away
from the explosions.
Yeah, that's pretty much it.
You know
something?
You're the first
person I've met
since I've been here
that hasn't made me feel
like I'm taking up
valuable bed space.
The way everyone looks at me...
I can't stand it.
After the court-martial's over,
I'm definitely signing up
for the next
mining expedition
to the Gamma Quadrant.
Maybe there won't be
a court-martial.
You're right.
None of us may get
out of here alive.
No, I mean Starfleet
could decide
to send you
to counseling instead.
I won't go.
I don't deserve
to be in Starfleet.
Therapy won't change
what I did.
Nothing will.
I just wish I had aimed
that phaser a little higher.
I saw the report
on Dr. Kalandra's desk.
According to Resource,
it's just a matter of time
before the Klingons
reach the compound.
I guess that means
I have to decide.
Decide what?
Whether I'd rather
get hacked to bits
or blasted by a disrupter.
A disrupter,
no doubt about it.
Every molecule in your body...
vaporized in a flash.
No time to feel pain.
Don't be so sure
about that.
Some people think
it's like being boiled alive.
Decapitation has its virtues.
Nice clean blow
with a sharp bat'leth.
The brain lives on
for five, ten seconds
at least.
In theory, your headless corpse
could be the last thing you see.
You're so negative.
I'm just telling you
what I heard.
What do you think, Jake?
I think it's not funny.
Well, of course not.
There's nothing funny
about having
your throat slit--
Cut it out!
I was just kidding.
JAKE:
You think this
is some joke.
It's not.
People are dying.
And it's all so stupid.
This whole stupid war
is such a waste.
In ten years, nobody's
going to remember
what anybody did here.
Jake...
Maybe you saved
a hopper full of people.
Maybe you shot yourself
in the foot.
No one's going
to remember!
Jake!
Let's take a walk.
I'm sorry.
Look, I know you're
scared, we all are.
No... it's not that.
What, Jake?
What is it?
I just didn't think
what they were saying was funny.
Come on, that's not
what set you off.
Something's eating at you.
I can see it.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Ever since you came back here,
you've been walking around
looking miserable.
Leave me alone.
Jake...
All right,
if that's what you want.
But if you want to talk,
you know where to find me.
( explosions )
What's going on?
Are they inside the compound?
Everybody, listen!
What's going on?
Listen!
We're evacuating.
We're taking the patients
out through the north tunnel
to the surface.
A hopper will take us
down the peninsula
to the base at Tanandra Bay.
That tunnel is almost
two kilometers long.
We have over 70
patients to move.
Do you know how long
that's going to take?
Resource is sending
a security detail
to defend the hospital
and give us
time to evacuate.
We can do this.
We have to keep calm,
focus on our jobs.
Those people out
there need us.
Yes. Let's move.
Come on.
Go.
( explosions )
Give me a hand!
Keep moving!
Two guards?!
Is that it?!
The others are out
defending the perimeter.
KIRBY:
Great. One's leaving.
We're going
someplace safe, all right.
Come on.
( explosions )
They're coming! Let's go!
Move! Move!
Come on, let's go!
Anyone left
back there?!
No.
Go! Go!
Get down!
( both yelling )
( yelling )
BASHIR:
Jake... look who's here.
Dad...
Don't move.
Let Dr. Bashir check
you for injuries.
What happened?
I came back for you
when I realized you
weren't on the hopper.
The cease-fire has
been reinstated.
The Klingons
are pulling out.
It's over.
The timing could have been
a little bit better,
but... uh, he seems
to be all right.
Sealing the entranceway
was a risky thing to do.
You nearly brought
the whole ceiling
down on yourself.
We never would have got
those patients out alive
if you hadn't
done it.
You're a hero.
JAKE:
More than anything,
I wanted to believe
what he was saying,
but the truth is,
I was just as scared
in the hospital
as I'd been when we went
for the generator,
so scared
that all I could think about
was doing whatever it took
to stay alive.
Once that meant running away,
and once it meant
picking up a phaser.
The battle of Ajilon Prime
will probably be remembered
as a pointless skirmish,
but I'll always remember it
as something more--
as the place I learned
that the line
between courage and cowardice
is a lot thinner
than most people believe.
I wasn't sure whether
to show it to you or not.
Hmm.
Anyone who's
been in battle
would recognize
himself in this,
but most of us wouldn't
care to admit it.
It takes courage
to look inside yourself,
and even more courage
to write it for
other people to see.
I'm proud of you, son.