You know, Morn,
there's nothing
more invigorating
than breakfast in a bar.
Where else can you
get raw slug liver
first thing
in the morning?
Mmm, mmm.
What's this?
What do you mean,
"what's this?"
It's puree of beetle.
I didn't order it.
Of course you didn't order it.
You don't need to order it.
You have it after work
every morning.
Well, I'm not having it
this morning.
I'd like...
two eggs over easy,
three strips of bacon,
and a side of corned beef hash.
What kind of breakfast is that?
It's Chief O'Brien's
breakfast of choice.
That's the problem
with working alongside hu-mans--
you pick up
their disgusting habits.
Bacon...
corned beef hash.
What's next, Rom?
Orange juice and coffee?
That might be nice.
( sighing )
I don't understand.
You gave up
a perfectly good job with me
to work on the station's
waste extraction system?
A good waste extraction system
is important.
Imagine where we'd be
without one.
Of course it's important,
but my point is
you're not getting
the choice assignments.
O'Brien's got you
on the night shift
doing all the work
nobody else wants to do.
I like my work.
You like standing
all night long,
knee-deep in waste,
fixing some broken
flow regulator
when you
could be here,
staring at half-naked
dabo girls?
I have a good job.
I'm proud of the work I do,
and I know that one day,
Chief O'Brien will recognize
my efforts
and reward me
with a position of respect
and responsibility,
and why?
Because that's just
the way things are
in Engineering.
( plate clatters )
I'm sorry I brought it up.
They don't look
so fine now.
I can't understand it.
I followed Keiko's instructions
to the letter.
They were dry as a bone
when I came by
for you yesterday.
I mean, I gave
them water.
I just don't think
it was enough.
You watered them?
These are Idran hybrids.
Too much water
rots their roots.
Oh.
( door opening )
Mommy's going to be mad.
I can't believe it.
Keiko's gone five days,
and we kill her plants.
She'll understand,
won't she?
I mean, after all,
they're just plants.
They're not just plants.
These are her bonsai trees.
She's cared for them,
and nurtured them
and carefully sculpted
their growth for months...
years.
You're in trouble.
Listen, Molly,
I think you and I
should both go
to the airlock
and welcome Mommy back,
and then after we've
hugged and kissed and...
you can tell her
what happened.
Not me.
Well, don't look at me.
Well, you killed
her plants.
We killed them.
But I think you're overreacting
to the situation.
I mean, Keiko
will forgive you.
It's your birthday today,
isn't it?
Yeah, so far, it's one
I'd like to forget.
Well, she's been
away on Bajor.
She's missed you.
Bring her a gift.
What kind of chocolates
does she like?
Tellurian mint truffles,
but I still think
you should be with me.
You don't need me there.
I've seen you handle your wife
thousands of times.
Just say you're sorry
and that you take
full responsibility.
You'll be fine.
Besides, I, uh...
have to be in surgery...
operating.
On who?
I'll find someone.
It was Julian.
He was trying
to be helpful.
He over-watered them.
It's not his fault.
You know how he is.
Sometimes he doesn't even
know what he's doing.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
We'll buy some new ones.
Forget it, Miles.
They're just plants.
Exactly.
It's not as if
something happened
to Molly or the baby.
Right, right.
I mean, everybody's fine.
No problems.
Good.
What about Kira?
Is she back yet?
No, she's still
with Shakaar.
They're traveling around
Dahkur Province.
I thought you were
going to visit them.
I didn't get a chance.
So, how are
the Fire Caves?
Fine.
And now it's time for me
to tell you some news.
I'm not Keiko.
No?
Who are you?
Listen carefully, Miles.
I have taken possession
of your wife's body.
I will hold it hostage
until you do everything
I tell you to
accurately,
and without question.
Hmm... everything?
If you don't do
precisely what I ask,
I'll kill your wife.
Are you all right?
Maybe there's
been an outbreak
of Rudellian brain
fever on Bajor.
We should go see Julian--
I see I'm going
to have to give you
a demonstration
of my sincerity.
( groaning and choking )
Keiko!
( choking )
No.
No, Miles.
You're not telling anyone.
If you do, I'll stop
her heart forever.
If you're really in
control my wife's body,
let me speak to her.
She can hear whatever
you have to say.
Not good enough.
I want to talk to her.
I want her
to talk to me.
You're in no position
to bargain, Miles.
Strange, these corporeal
bodies of yours-- so fragile.
Burst even a tiny blood vessel
in the brain,
and every memory,
every passionate emotion--
gone forever.
You really shouldn't let me
eat all these by myself, Miles.
I'm not hungry.
Look, why don't
you just tell me
what it is you
want me to do
so we can get
this over with.
Very well.
But let me make
one thing clear:
I will not do anything
to jeopardize this station
or the people on it.
Don't worry, Miles.
All I want you to
do is reconfigure
some of the
communication
and sensor relays
on the station.
Why?
I can't tell you.
You'll have to be patient.
The communications
and sensor relays
are distributed throughout
the entire station.
You know your wife
well, Miles,
but she knows
you even better.
I know you're just
playing for time
until you can get
to your friends--
Julian, Dax,
Captain Sisko.
I know they'll all
want to help you.
The Captain may
even allow you
to do what I'm asking,
at least until
someone figures out
a way to catch me
in some sort of stasis field
or some other clever device
you're already dreaming up.
And you know what?
It might work.
You might be able to stop me,
but I promise you one thing:
If you do, Keiko will die.
All I need
is a split second
to cause a massive
brain hemorrhage, and...
she's gone.
I know this is a difficult
adjustment for you to make,
but we don't have a lot of time.
What do you want me to do?
KEIKO:
How long is this
going to take?
In order to keep
the polarity shift
invisible to
security checks,
I'm going to
have to tap into
the optronic integrator
on Level Five.
You're the engineer.
What is it, Miles?
What do you want
to ask me?
You always tighten
your brow just a tiny bit
whenever you're about
to ask a question.
It's something
only a wife would notice.
Why Keiko?
Why take control of her?
Why not me?
I'm the one who can do the work.
It would be more efficient.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
Yes, you are.
We're busy.
Miles, don't be so rude.
Aw, Bajoran spiny basil--
how thoughtful.
It's the least
I could do after...
Oh, it's all
right, Julian.
I forgive you.
Now, you are coming
to the party tonight,
aren't you?
BASHIR:
I'll be here.
I guess it's not
a surprise anymore.
Oh, I can't believe
I did that.
I arranged a birthday
dinner for you tonight,
but I wanted it
to be a surprise.
Well, that's okay.
I... I don't like surprises.
Well, I better be going.
I left a patient
on the operating table.
I'll see you later.
Thanks, Julian.
This was so sweet.
No problem.
A party? Tonight?
It is your birthday.
We can't have
all those people here.
We'll have to cancel.
And raise suspicions?
It's better if the dinner
goes on as planned.
Besides, Keiko
went to a lot of trouble
to arrange it for you.
Now, you better
get back to work.
You don't want to be late
for your shift briefing,
and I've got a lot
of cooking to do.
( sighing )
Diagnostic and Repair Technician
Junior Grade Rom reporting.
Right. You're Duarte's
replacement. Have a seat.
I'm on the swing shift?
For a day or two.
WOMAN:
What's the matter
with Duarte?
MALE:
Sick as a vole.
Is this where Duarte sits?
So, what are you drinking?
Raktajino.
Great.
Is that what we drink
on the swing shift?
You can drink
anything you want.
I'll have a raktajino.
It's not like this
on the night shift.
We don't drink raktajino.
We really don't drink anything.
Fascinating.
Change of plans today, people.
I need to recalibrate
the optronic integrator
on Level Five.
What is it, Rom?
I volunteer.
I like phase-shifting
reconfigurations.
Thank you, but I'll
take care of that myself.
I want the rest of you
to concentrate
on the new inertial couplings.
I want all 64 couplings
done today.
Watley, you and Tekoa
cover the docking ring.
Abdon and Nori, the cargo bays.
Rom, the upper pylons.
Any questions?
Good.
Now, since I'll be
working alone today,
I'm going to be very busy,
so I don't want
to be interrupted
by anything unimportant.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Computer...
locate Keiko O'Brien.
COMPUTER: Keiko O'Brien
is in her quarters.
Computer, initiate full
identity scan of Keiko O'Brien
and note any inconsistencies
with existing medical records.
COMPUTER: Scan complete.
No inconsistencies found.
Identity confirmed.
How long would it take
a level-3 stasis field
to render Keiko O'Brien
unconscious?
COMPUTER: All cognitive reflexes
would cease in 2.1 seconds.
Too long.
Calculate the time
if anesthetine gas were used.
COMPUTER:
1.4 seconds.
What about a phaser set on stun?
COMPUTER: 0.9 seconds.
God help me.
JAKE:
There you
are, Chief.
I was beginning to think
you were going to miss
your own party.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I had a few odds
and ends to tie up.
Have you seen Keiko?
Oh, she's in the bedroom
helping Molly try on
different shoes--
a little fashion crisis.
But as usual, your wife
has handled everything.
You're a lucky man, Miles.
Keiko has really
outdone herself this time.
Take it from an old cook--
Q'parol is a very
time-consuming dish.
( door opens )
Happy birthday, Daddy!
♪ For... ♪
ALL:
♪ He's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For he's
a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ Which nobody can deny. ♪
Happy birthday,
sweetheart.
Make a wish.
( all applauding )
KEIKO:
Single malt Irish whiskey.
Neat.
Molly wanted to wear
her new purple shoes for you.
Doesn't she look pretty?
Very pretty.
Now all the food's set out
on the table,
so just relax with your friends
and I'll pass these around.
( softly ):
I want to talk to you.
Not right now, Miles.
We have guests.
( door opens )
Sorry I'm late.
Dax, I was afraid
you weren't coming.
Well, I heard you
were serving Q'parol,
and how could
I miss it?
What's the matter, Chief?
You look a little
preoccupied.
Everything all right?
Well, there's, um...
there's something
I forgot to tell Keiko.
Would you excuse me
for a moment?
Of course.
Did you see
any Pah-wraiths?
Pah-wraiths?
In the Fire Caves.
Odo was telling me
the Caves
were haunted by some
sort of weird
supernatural beings.
Don't tell me you believe
in wraiths.
ODO:
Well, I may
have mentioned
the Bajoran legends
about creatures living
in the caves,
but I never said
I believe in them.
Well, the only thing
I saw in the caves
were some beautiful and
botanically fascinating fungi.
JAKE:
Well,
maybe the next time
you go to the Fire Caves,
I could come along.
I've always wanted
to meet a Pah-wraith.
Maybe you will.
You never know.
I've done what you asked.
That's terrific, Miles.
We'll talk later.
MOLLY:
Can I have cake now?
KEIKO:
Oh, in a bit, sweetie.
( groans )
Miles, are you
bleeding?
No. It's...
it's nothing.
Let me take a look.
I said I'm all right!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, everybody.
Excuse me.
Get ahold of yourself.
Look, I've done
everything
you've asked me to do.
Just give me back my wife.
You've done well, Miles,
but recalibrating the optronic
integrator was only a test.
I had to be sure
I could trust you.
Tomorrow the real work begins.
Now it's time to get back
to our guests.
We don't want
to raise suspicions, do we?
Is Molly asleep?
Yes.
The Q'parol was a huge success.
Look, no more tests,
no more games.
Just tell me
what you want done.
We'll talk about it
in the morning.
It's late and
you're working
a double shift
tomorrow.
I want to talk about it now!
Miles, I make the rules.
Now relax.
Everything's going to be fine
as long as you do what I ask.
I'll sleep on the couch.
Don't be childish.
What if Molly has one
of her nightmares
and comes running in?
You'll sleep in bed with me
just like you always do.
I'll be there
in a minute.
Don't be too late.
You've got a busy day tomorrow.
Computer...
give me the record
of all Bajoran legends
concerning the Pah-wraiths.
COMPUTER: There are 6,427
entries in the data banks
that reference that subject.
Please specify.
KEIKO:
Miles?
Sleep well.
( sighs )
Another weakness
of you corporeal life-forms--
your need for physical intimacy.
It's especially irritating
in your young.
I have to get Molly
ready for school.
I'll do it.
You have a big day ahead of you.
Molly is going to sleep over
at the Davis' tonight,
and she's staying there
until this is over.
You really think that's wise?
A little girl needs her mother.
Molly would be lost
without hers.
You stay away from her.
Miles, I'd never do anything
to hurt your daughter...
unless you force me to.
These are your instructions.
Follow them precisely.
Computer, locate Captain Sisko.
Captain Sisko is in Security.
Miles?
No!
ODO:
And you didn't see anyone
near her before she fell?
Nobody, but I was passing
underneath the walkway,
and I had my back toward her.
What were you doing
on the Promenade?
What?
Weren't you supposed
to be working
on optronic circuitry
on Level Five?
I was going to the Replimat
for lunch.
BASHIR:
Keiko is going
to be all right.
She's lucky that she landed
the way that she did.
It distributed the impact.
Otherwise, a fall
from that height
could easily have killed her
or left her paralyzed.
Is she conscious?
Yes, but she's
still in shock.
She has a broken femur
and a hairline fracture
of the right
parietal lobe.
Can I see her?
Maybe in a couple of hours.
Right now, she
needs to rest.
Julian...
I really need
to see her now.
Doctor.
All right...
but only for
a few minutes.
Don't excite her.
Keiko?
You were going
to tell them about me.
How did you know?
I know everything
your wife knows,
and she knows you.
I told you we have
to trust one another.
You violated that trust.
Now look where it's led us.
I want my wife back,
do you hear? I want her...
Then stop trying
to fool me.
How much more damage do you
think this body can take?
Now...
no more tricks.
Agreed?
Say it.
Agreed.
Good.
You know what you need to do.
You should get back to work.
I'll have everything completed
in 36 hours.
You have 13 and not
a minute more.
I can't do it that fast.
You're a very
resourceful man.
I'm sure you can
find a way...
for Keiko's sake.
You bloody...
She does need to rest, Chief.
Tell Molly I'll
be home soon.
Tell her
Mommy's fine.
Don't scare her.
Miles...
give me a kiss.
I'm counting on you.
She'll be back on her feet soon,
I promise.
Computer, begin a 13-hour
countdown, starting now.
COMPUTER:
Clock activated.
Chief.
I heard about
Keiko's accident.
How is she?
Julian said
she'll be home soon.
That is good.
If there is anything
I can do...
I wish there was.
I really do.
I'd better get going.
I'm falling behind schedule.
Computer, time remaining?
Eight hours, 22 minutes,
three seconds.
Chief!
( gasps )
Sorry.
I didn't mean
to startle you.
Rom, what are you
doing here?
Reporting for my
next assignment.
I've completed
calibration tests
on the inertial
coupling ports
on all three
upper pylons.
Already?
How did you finish
so quickly?
I just did the work.
I didn't allow myself
to get caught up
in any of the
distracting discussions
the other workers
engage in.
Ferengi can be
very focused,
especially when no one
bothers to talk to them.
I see.
Not that I mind.
I'm used to being ignored.
Is something wrong, Chief?
I can work slower
if you want me to.
Rom...
I need your help,
and I need you to
keep your mouth shut.
Can I count on you?
Is that
a trick question?
Rom, this is serious.
You can depend
on me, Chief.
We're going to make
some modifications
to several
of the station's systems.
I don't want you to breathe
a word of this to anyone.
That includes Dax, Odo,
Captain Sisko,
Worf...
They don't know?
Of course they know.
Well, at least some of them do,
but they have to pretend
that they don't.
This is a top secret
Starfleet operation.
Culpable deniability.
I understand.
Don't worry about me, Chief.
My lips are sealed.
Nobody will get anything
out of me.
Not even my name.
Rom, everybody on the station
knows your name.
Right.
But I won't confirm it.
Where do we start?
Computer, time remaining?
Six hours, 41 minutes,
26 seconds.
DAX:
Chief...
Commander, what are you
doing up at this hour?
I want you to have
a look at something.
I couldn't sleep,
so I got up and decided
to scan the wormhole
for radiometric anomalies.
At 3:00 in the morning?
I've always found anomalies
to be very relaxing.
It's a curse.
I was using the wideband
filter protocols,
and when I ran
the primary calibrations check,
I found this.
Oh, they're
slightly off spec.
Yes. I thought it might be
a fused matrix inverter
until I ran
a level-3 diagnostic.
Have a look.
We'd better wake
the Captain.
We have a saboteur
on the station.
All right, what have we got?
Computer, display diagnostic.
Chief?
We've identified
943 tiny fluctuations
in the primary
communication relays
and several power
distribution junctions.
Fluctuations that
can't be attributed
to anything except
external intervention.
Someone's gained
access to our systems
and is altering them.
For what purpose?
We're working on that.
At this point, it's hard
to even call it sabotage.
There's been no real damage.
The systems are just
a little off spec.
So far, these alterations
don't seem
to pose any threat
to the station.
So far.
But this might
be just the tip
of a very large
and dangerous iceberg.
Is there any way to trace how
this was done, and by whom?
It has to be someone familiar
with the station's systems.
Maybe someone who worked
on the station
under the Cardassians.
I'm running extensive
security checks
on all recent visitors,
but so far, I haven't
found anything.
DAX:
It could have been someone
who's been on the station
a long time--
someone with
a lot of access.
Maybe even someone
on the maintenance crew.
Chief?
Yes.
Yes, what?
Do you think
it's someone
on your staff?
( beeping )
MAN: Chief O'Brien, I have
a call from your daughter.
Go ahead.
Molly, honey, what is it?
Hi, Daddy. Mommy told
me I could call you.
I hope we didn't interrupt
anything important.
It's all right, Molly.
I'm glad you called.
What are you doing at home?
She missed her mommy.
Isn't that sweet?
When are you
going to come...?
Ow, Mommy! That hurt.
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetie.
Are you all right, Molly?
She's fine, Miles.
She just wants to know
when you'll be finished.
I told her
you had to work
another two hours,
22 minutes and 13 seconds.
MOLLY:
How long is that, Daddy?
Soon.
I'll be home very soon.
Good.
We both miss you.
Everything all right?
Fine. I'm sorry about
the interruption.
You were saying
you thought you knew
who the saboteur
might be.
I think I have an idea.
Hello, Constable.
Hello, Chief.
What are you doing, Rom?
I can't talk about it.
Oh, yes, you can.
And you will.
Coming, Chief?
I'd better see what
he's been up to here.
I'll take care of those.
( sighs in frustration )
Has he said anything?
Not much.
For the first
40 minutes, it was
like pulling teeth
even getting him
to admit his name.
You think he's
working alone?
I don't know.
Rom admits to nothing.
Now he's asking
to see Chief O'Brien.
He won't talk
to anybody else.
Then get the Chief
down here.
I want to know
what's going on.
Security to Chief O'Brien.
O'BRIEN:
Go ahead, Constable.
We need you in Security
right away.
I'm still trying to figure out
what Rom did to these systems.
ODO:
That'll have to wait.
I have Captain's orders to get
you down here immediately.
On my way.
Computer, time remaining?
COMPUTER:
36 minutes, nine seconds.
Computer, locate
Maintenance Technician Rom.
COMPUTER:
Maintenance Technician Rom
is in Security Holding Cell
Number Four.
Initiate security override
and scramble surveillance
channels 4-A, B, C and D.
Authorization:
O'Brien-seven-one-two.
COMPUTER: Specified security
channels scrambled.
Now begin recalibration
of gravitic sensors
at Access Panel 379
as indicated.
I'll be back in ten minutes.
The Chief is here, Rom.
Now, what do you want
to say?
Alone.
I'll only talk if we're alone.
What is it, Rom?
It's okay-- I've disconnected
Odo's eavesdropping devices.
I haven't told anyone anything,
just like you said.
You're a good man.
Now, why did you call me?
I told you we're under
very tight time constraints.
Captain Sisko is really angry.
If I didn't know
he was pretending--
Rom...
Don't worry.
I can hold out
until you say otherwise,
but there is
one thing I have to know.
Go ahead.
Why are we focusing
a chroniton beam
at the wormhole?
What?
The new frequency
of the deflector grid
is set to turn the station
into a massive chroniton array
aimed directly at the wormhole.
So, I just wanted to know...
why are we trying to kill
the wormhole aliens?
What are you
talking about?
The chroniton beam
is harmless.
To us, but its
temporal disruption
would kill a wormhole
alien instantly.
Of course.
Why didn't I think of that?
She has me so on edge,
I haven't been able to see
the forest for the trees.
Who's she?
I don't have time
to explain now.
The question is:
Why would anyone want to kill
the wormhole aliens?
Everyone has enemies,
even the Prophets.
That's right.
They're not just
wormhole aliens, they're...
they're Prophets
part of Bajoran mythology...
just like the Pah-wraiths
of the Fire Caves.
So...
what have those wraiths
got to do
with the wormhole aliens?
Koss'moran.
What?
It's a Bajoran legend.
From the verb kosst
meaning "to be"
and amoran--
"banished."
Leeta's been telling me
all about Bajoran legends.
She can go on for hours.
She says I'm a good listener.
I'm sure you are.
Now it's time to be
a good talker-- go on.
Well, uh, according to Leeta,
the Pah-wraiths used to live
in the wormhole.
They were part
of the Celestial Temple.
They were Prophets.
False Prophets.
They were cast out
of the Temple,
exiled to the Caves,
where they were imprisoned
in crystal fire cages
and forbidden to ever return
"lest they face the wrath
of the true Prophets."
So if these false Prophets
were to return
to the Celestial Temple...
I don't think
they'd be welcomed.
Unless... she kills
all the wormhole aliens first.
Rom... I'm going to have
to leave you in a tough spot.
Captain Sisko, Odo--
they don't know
about any of this, do they?
No. No, they don't,
and I want you to help me
keep it that way
for a little while longer.
I have to stay here
and play the idiot?
I'm afraid so.
Now, no matter
what Odo asks you...
I'm Quark's brother.
I know the role.
( sighs )
Computer, time remaining?
12 minutes, 22 seconds.
( Odo clears throat )
Sorry to disturb you, Chief.
Couple of things
are still bothering me.
Rom couldn't have
done all this sabotage alone.
There were too many changes
for any one person to make.
Maybe so.
Right now, I've got a frequency
problem in the cascade feeder.
I checked with the repair logs.
I was hoping to match
someone's movements
to the locations
where the alterations were made,
but I couldn't do that.
We had a matrix systems
failure yesterday.
Those files were lost.
Sorry.
Hmm. We've had a lot
of systems failures recently,
haven't we, Chief?
Really?
I hadn't noticed.
I've been too busy
repairing things.
Like the surveillance channels
in the holding cells?
You authorized
a security override.
What was wrong with them?
The fiber optic relay
was out of sync.
The isolinear chip
junction was...
Enough, Chief.
You didn't cover your tracks
very well.
Why?
I didn't have time.
I still don't.
( groans )
Sorry, Odo.
Chief O'Brien to Keiko O'Brien.
This is Keiko.
I've finished,
but we have to move quickly.
This place is going to be
swarming with Security.
Meet me
at Runabout Pad C now.
KEIKO: How did you know
I'd want a runabout?
Because I know
what you're planning to do,
but don't worry,
I don't give a damn
about the Celestial Temple
or your non-corporeal feuds.
I just want my wife back.
Now, you still need me to
pilot you to the wormhole.
So let's stop wasting time.
Agreed?
KEIKO:
I'll meet you there.
That's correct, Commander.
I want to test
some new magnetic constrictors
in the runabout's impulse
thrusters.
DAX:
Very well, Chief.
You're cleared for departure,
but before you go,
there's one thing
I'd like to ask you.
What's that?
DAX:
Did you enjoy your birthday?
Well, it was full of surprises.
DAX: Good.
Those are always my favorites.
Hold position here.
Computer, initiate modifications
O'Brien-731
and enable remote com link.
COMPUTER:
Com link enabled.
( alarm blaring )
What the hell?
Target the center
of the wormhole.
Target coordinates set.
Have us face the Temple.
The blast will last
only a fraction of a second.
They'll all be dead
before they even see it.
Oh! You have no idea
how many centuries
I've waited for this.
Let's get on with it!
Miles, you have a lot to learn
about patience.
Proceed.
SISKO:
Chief, what's going on
out there?
I'm ordering you to return
to the station.
Now.
Activate.
( screams )
( screaming )
Keiko?
Miles...
( relieved sighs )
Chief...
you have some
explaining to do.
It was more like
having something
coiled around
inside my head.
I could see and hear
through it,
but anytime I tried
to do anything...
it was like being stuck
in sand and squeezed.
Yeah.
Could you sense
any of its thoughts?
Just feelings, sometimes.
Kind of a cold rage.
I don't think it had
any intention
of leaving either one of us
alive.
You don't have to talk about
it if you don't want to.
Oh, it feels better
to talk about it.
Besides, I don't want to forget
how hard you fought for me.
Hello, Brother.
You look horrible.
I'm telling you, Rom,
working the night shift
is driving you
to an early grave.
I wasn't working.
What do you mean
you weren't working?
I'm not on
the night shift anymore.
I knew it.
O'Brien fired you.
No, Brother.
In appreciation
of my work,
the Chief... has promoted me
to the day shift.
He says I have a promising
future in engineering.
Then why do you look so tired?
I was out
celebrating.
With who?
My crewmates.
I think they like me.
Do they?
Especially Litana.
She's always finding excuses
to talk to me.
Well, Rom...
I'm glad things are going
so well for you.
No, you're not,
but thanks anyway, Brother.
I guess you'll be wanting
the "Chief's Special" again?
Actually, no.
I've discovered that bacon
doesn't agree with me.
What a surprise.
Instead
I'll have
a short stack of pancakes,
dripping with butter,
a side of sausage,
and... pineapple.
Pineapple?
That's the breakfast
of choice on the day shift.
Pineapple.
( sighs )