So, what do you think
of the O'Briens' plan
to name their baby Sean?
Well, I kind of like it.
Sean... has a nice ring to it.
Except that in Bajoran
sean means "swamp."
Do the O'Briens know that?
I doubt it.
Someone should tell them.
I nominate you.
DAX:
Morning.
Neck bothering you again?
It's... it's just a muscle pull.
What is that?
The eighth muscle pull
this month?
Actually, I believe
Commander Dax has been treated
for seven muscle pulls,
two contusions, and
three cracked ribs.
The only person who's spent
more time in the Infirmary
over the past few weeks
is... Commander Worf.
Isn't there any way the...
the two of you could, uh...
uh, you know...
Make love?
Without injuring yourselves?
Interspecies romance
isn't without its danger.
That's part of the fun.
Maybe we'll have
better luck on Risa.
Risa?
I thought you and Worf
were taking your
vacation on Earth.
That was his suggestion.
I changed his mind.
ODO:
From what I hear
Risa make the Hoobishan Baths
look like a monastery.
I hope they have
a good hospital.
( chuckling )
SISKO:
I can't believe
you actually convinced Worf
to go to a pleasure planet.
He must really be loosening up.
I hadn't noticed it.
Come to think of it,
neither have I.
Oh, no, he's still
the same old Worf.
Prune juice, extra large.
See what I mean?
Worf.
Captain, Constable...
Commander.
Uh, Dax said...
you were going to Risa.
Did she?
Well, it's no secret.
Apparently not.
You must be
looking forward to it.
I'm looking forward
to spending some time alone
with Lieutenant Commander Dax.
Isn't he sweet?
We have much to discuss.
About what?
It is a private matter.
Oh.
DAX:
Worf's upset
because I had lunch
with Captain Boday.
The Gallamite?
His skull is transparent.
And if you couldn't see
his brains,
would it make you
feel any better?
It is not proper
for you to have lunch
with an ex-lover
while we are together.
We were just talking.
You have to learn
to trust me a little more.
WORF:
I do trust you.
I do not trust Captain Boday.
Well...
I can see it's going to be
quite a trip.
Well, the two of you
have to tell us
all about it
when you get back.
I am sure she will.
I do not see why you
feel the need to talk
about our personal lives
to other people.
And I don't see why
you feel the need
to control my every move.
And they're not other people.
Benjamin and Odo are my friends.
BASHIR:
Jadzia.
Hey.
Worf.
We've been looking for you.
Um, I've been thinking
about this trip
you're taking
to Risa.
He's a friend, too.
LEETA:
Julian and I
were talking it over,
and we'd like
to come along...
if that's all right.
Actually, we were hoping
to spend some time
alone together.
Oh, you'll have it.
Oh, once we get to Risa,
you won't even see us.
There's no harm
in sharing a runabout.
I suppose not.
Oh!
Thank you so much!
I'm going
to go pack.
Commander...
Do not hug me.
I promise we'll keep
out of your hair.
Good.
Because we have
much to discuss.
I really wish
I was going with you.
Dax and I had
some great times on Risa.
( laughing )
Curzon Dax.
Curzon.
Of course.
Have fun.
It's about time you got here.
The rest of us were ready
to leave an hour ago.
What is he doing here?
I've always wanted
to go to Risa,
and this seemed like
a perfect opportunity.
He wouldn't
give me any time off
unless we promised
to take him with us.
I hope this isn't
going to be a problem.
QUARK:
Why should it
be a problem?
We're going to have
a wonderful time.
Now, if you don't mind,
Risa awaits.
Sorry.
Jadzia...
I know, I know.
We have much to discuss.
Let's see... that's
a Tarkalean tea for you,
a raktajino for you,
and an extra large
prune juice.
Leeta, you're on vacation,
not at Quark's.
You don't have
to serve us.
Oh, it gives me
something to do.
Space travel's so dull.
Have you ever noticed
how all stars look the same?
Excuse me...
but I believe I ordered
a snail juice--
hand-squeezed.
Get it yourself.
I'm on vacation.
How much longer
till we get there?
DAX:
Another six hours.
QUARK:
Six hours?
Tell the Ferengi
to return to his cabin.
You call that a cabin?
It's a cot
and a waste disposal unit.
It's so small
even I can't stand up in there.
Look-- I'm developing a slouch.
Tell the Ferengi
to return to his cabin now.
Quark...
What's he going to do?
Turn around
and take me home?
Ruin everyone's vacation?
Coming about.
Setting course
for Deep Space 9.
Okay, okay.
You made your point.
I'm going.
But first, I have
a little present for everyone.
One for you.
And one for you.
And none for you.
What's this?
It's a Horga'hn.
A Risian fertility symbol.
Displaying one
to the locals
indicates you're
seeking jamaharon.
LEETA:
What's jamaharon?
I'll show you later.
Oh.
Look.
They like each other.
I think I'm going
to be sick.
All right. I'm going.
Me, too.
Going? Where?
I'm going to change
into something more comfortable.
You don't think
I'm going to beam down to Risa
dressed like this, do you?
That's a good idea.
When in Rome...
( sighs )
Oh!
I can't believe
we finally made it.
Well, enjoy your vacation.
Mmm. We will.
Time to test
these babies out.
Ladies...
You seek jamaharon?
I seek whatever you've got.
All that is ours
is yours.
I'll take it.
Aren't you uncomfortable
in that uniform?
Starfleet uniforms
are designed for comfort,
even in the most
extreme environments.
Well, you look
out of place.
I mean, look around you.
Isn't it beautiful?
It is an artificially
created paradise,
maintained by the most elaborate
weather control system
in the Federation.
In its natural state,
Risa is nothing more
than a rain-soaked,
geologically
unstable jungle.
Maybe so,
but the only dark cloud
I see around here is you.
I did not come here
to admire the scenery.
If you say so.
I guess we should
just go home.
Well, maybe...
I would not be so hasty.
I take it
the scenery has improved.
A few months ago
when I was commanding
the Defiant
on a scouting mission
in the Gamma Quadrant,
we encountered
a protostar cluster--
a swirling mass of color
set against
a background
of glowing clouds
and burning sky.
It was the most beautiful thing
I'd ever seen...
until now.
I've got to take you
on vacation more often.
Dax, is that you?
Arandis.
I was wondering
if you were still here.
Oh!
Not only am I still here,
I have been promoted.
I'm Chief Facilitator for
the entire Temtibi Lagoon.
Worf, this is Arandis.
A friend
of Curzon's.
She and Curzon spent
a lot of time together
on his last trip here.
We had a wonderful time
together...
until I killed him.
Killed him?!
Death by jamaharon.
I suppose there
are worse ways to go.
Trust me, he died happy.
He was such a sweet old man.
I will take your word for it.
It's so good
to see you again, Dax.
Your new host
is very attractive.
Thank you.
I'd like to think so.
You haven't aged
a day.
Ah... Risa's been
very kind to me.
Come, let me
show you around.
Maybe later.
Of course.
All that is ours is yours.
Thank you.
But we have everything we need.
That wasn't very nice.
Why? Is there something
of hers you want?
Arandis was Curzon's lover,
not mine.
I hope you
remember that.
You're still angry
about Captain Boday.
If I am angry, it is because
you do not take our
relationship seriously.
Worf, we just got here.
Do we have
to start arguing again?
If you were a Klingon woman,
we would already be married.
In case you haven't noticed,
I am not a Klingon woman.
That is no excuse.
I have been loyal to you,
and I expect you to be loyal
to me in return.
I have been loyal to you,
but I'm not going
to let you run my life.
I'm not trying to run your life.
Then I'm going to go
and have a big glass
of icoberry juice.
That is a mistake.
You are allergic
to icoberry juice.
It makes your...
spots itch.
But I like the taste.
Fine. Have as much
icoberry juice as you like,
but it is still a mistake.
But it is my mistake
to make.
Now, why don't you
go up to our room
and put on your bathing suit
so we can swim in the lagoon?
As you wish.
( door chimes )
Enter.
I hope I'm not disturbing you,
Lieutenant Commander.
My name is
Pascal Fullerton.
I'm the chairman of the
New Essentialists Movement.
I'm not familiar
with that organization.
We're dedicated to restoring
the moral and cultural
traditions of the Federation.
This is a statement
of our principles.
But if you would
like to hear more,
we're holding a rally
later this afternoon.
On Risa?
What better place?
This world revels in the kind
of self-indulgence
that's eroding the foundations
of Federation society.
We intend to shut it down.
I really wish you'd
stop reading that.
I would not dismiss
Fullerton so quickly.
His analysis
of recent Federation history
is both insightful
and disturbing.
What's really
disturbing
is that you're still
wearing your uniform.
It would not hurt you
to read this.
LEETA:
Mmm...
mmm!
Well, the truth is
not everyone can
be a dabo girl.
First of all,
you have to be able
to wear the clothes,
and believe me,
that's not easy.
You have to be able
to calculate odds in
your head very quickly,
and most importantly,
you need a very
supple wrist...
like this.
Dabo.
DAX:
...the end of
the Federation
since the day
it was founded.
Trust me. I know.
Oh, hi!
Leeta, what a surprise.
Care to join us?
We were just about
to take a reyamilk soak.
Maybe later.
Worf.
( sigh of contentment )
That was not Dr. Bashir.
It's none of our business.
Are you defending
her actions?
I am not
defending anything,
but it's not my
business or yours.
Now, what do you
say we go sign out
a couple of floaters
and take in the sights?
I cannot.
The Essentialists
are having a rally,
and I plan to attend.
( sighs ):
You're kidding.
You're not kidding.
Don't these people have
anything better to do?
Perhaps you
underestimate
the power of
Fullerton's message.
The plot thickens.
And you were worried
about Julian.
Why are he and Leeta
not together?
I don't know, but don't
jump to conclusions.
I'm sure there's
a reasonable explanation.
This place is
a bad influence on people.
ARANDIS:
Here for the show?
I would not call it
a show.
Really? I find Mr. Fullerton
very entertaining.
He seems
pretty determined
to discourage people
from coming here.
Risa receives millions
of visitors every year.
And all of them leave happier
than when they've arrived.
I don't see how one man,
no matter how determined,
can change that.
Kahless fought off an entire
army at Three Turn Bridge,
and he was only one man.
Fullerton and his
Essentialists
have been here
for about a month,
and no matter
how many speeches he gives,
the water's still warm,
and the wind still smells sweet.
But, if he's enjoying himself,
who are we to discourage him?
( scattered applause )
That's right.
Take a good look.
I can only imagine
what you must think of me--
a middle-aged,
ponderous academic,
sweating under
the hot Risian suns,
wasting his time
telling you things
you don't want
to hear.
But you know what I see
when I look at you?
Children...
pampered, spoiled children.
For some reason, the
citizens of the Federation
have come to believe
that they are entitled
to lives of ease....
I may be wrong,
but didn't he
just insult us?
If you want
something to eat,
you get it from
a replicator.
If you want amusement,
you go to a holosuite,
and if you need protection,
you call for Starfleet.
But someday...
someday soon,
you're going to
have to learn
to take care
of yourselves,
because if I see you
as helpless children,
then how do you think
the Borg see you?
Or the Romulans or the Klingons
or the Dominion?
These empires look
at the Federation,
and they see a prize--
a prize that we have
forgotten how to protect,
and if we don't change our ways,
they're going to take it
from us.
Mr. Fullerton has quite
a flair for the dramatic.
Does he really believe that?
I think he does.
...and re-embrace
the kind of hard work
that built the Federation
in the first place.
Or we can lie here,
napping in the sun,
until we wake up
with Jem'Hadar guns
to our heads.
The choice is ours.
Heaven help us
if we make the wrong one.
BASHIR:
What are you
talking about?
Come on, Worf, this sounds
like nonsense.
I am merely observing
that the Klingons would
never have attacked
had they not believed
the Federation vulnerable.
Even now, since
the changeling
was discovered on the
Klingon High Council,
most of my people
continue to call for war,
because they think
they can win.
None of this has
anything to do with Risa.
You cannot be certain of that.
DAX:
All I know is
I've spent lifetimes
defending the Federation,
and I deserve a vacation
every now and then.
Julian?
Oh, there you are.
I am so glad we came here.
I'm having
the most wonderful time.
I told you this was
just what we needed.
Mmm...
Something wrong?
It's nothing.
You two dishonor each other
with your actions.
Do you know
what he's talking about?
You mean... we didn't tell you
why we came here?
We're conducting
the Rite of Separation.
It's an old Bajoran custom.
When a couple separates,
they spend several days
celebrating their parting.
It's a way to remember
all the good times
and to seek out
new opportunities.
A very wise and ancient culture.
LEETA:
You know, Julian,
I don't think
I've completely gotten you
out of my system yet.
I know exactly
what you mean.
Excuse us.
Um, we have a few...
details to work out.
Terminating
a relationship
should not be taken
so frivolously.
Not every relationship
has to end like
a Klingon opera.
Oh, no, no.
Just the ones that
are important.
( furniture breaking )
Stay where you are.
On three.
One, two...
Wait.
That's enough.
Well... I hope
we've proved our point.
The power cells
are empty.
We have no intention
of harming anyone.
I don't understand.
You think you're safe here
in this "paradise" of yours,
but you're not.
What if we had been Jem'Hadar
or Klingons
or Romulans.
Hmm?
You'd be dead now.
Even you-- Starfleet officers--
were lulled into a false
sense of security.
If you could be taken unaware,
what chance
do the rest of us have?
The sad truth is
the galaxy is a hostile place.
Forget that, even for a moment,
and you risk losing everything.
Just something
for you
to think about while you wait
for your desserts.
All right.
Come on, demonstration's over.
Move along, move along.
As a Starfleet officer,
I have the authority
to arrest you
for what you just did.
But that would be
a waste of time.
We both know the Risians
won't prosecute.
They don't have
the courage for it.
Believe me, I wish they did.
Commander Worf...
what did you think of
our little demonstration?
I cannot condone
what you have done.
Maybe not...
but I do think
you understand it.
( sighs )
I don't know about you,
but it's past my bedtime.
We need to talk.
About the Essentialists?
No. About us.
Oh, I suppose you have another
list of things I'm doing wrong.
I did not say you were
doing anything wrong.
It's just that...
some of your behavior...
What about my behavior?
At times, you are too impulsive.
You-you act without thinking.
You have no
self-control.
And you think
I need you to control me?
Jadzia, you are my par'machkai,
and that means everything
you do reflects on me.
I'm sorry if I embarrass you.
I just need to know
that you take this relationship
as seriously
as I do.
And I just wish
you'd relax a little
and let yourself enjoy
what we have together.
Worf, I'm not going
to change who I am.
Nor am I.
Well, at least we agree
on something.
( sighs )
Why don't we go to bed?
You go.
I will be there shortly.
( sighs )
This place looks
a lot better
than it did
last night.
I guess the Risians
aren't as lethargic
as the Essentialists would
like everyone to believe.
The Essentialists are
wrong about many things.
What Mr. Fullerton could use
is a little jamaharon.
No...
a lot of jamaharon.
I'd buy him a Horga'hn myself
if I thought he'd take it.
( sighs )
It looks like
he's not the only one
that could use some cheering up.
I've had better vacations.
Better than Risa?
( sighs )
I've never known a Klingon
who had a tougher time
enjoying himself.
That's no reason for you
not to have a good time.
Risa is famous
for its diversions.
I wish it were that simple.
It was for Curzon Dax.
Yeah.
And I can tell
there's more
than a little Curzon in you.
He loved this planet.
And Risa loved him.
Why don't I help you clean up?
All that is ours is yours.
LEETA:
Our paths have grown apart.
What was one is now two.
The time for sharing
is over.
May the Prophets guide you
toward the path of happiness.
And may they walk
with you always.
That's it?
That's it.
What were
you expecting?
I was expecting
fireworks.
Where's the anger?
The vicious
name-calling?
The irrational
accusations?
I never would have agreed
to be a witness
if I'd known you were going
to be so civil.
It's disgusting.
Personally, I think
it was admirable--
no recriminations,
no hurt feelings.
I don't think I've
ever felt this good
about the end
of a relationship.
Oh, I agree.
Now I can finally be honest
about my feelings.
What... does
that mean?
It's just...
in the past
few months,
I've been... thinking a lot
about another man.
Ahh...
Let me get
this straight.
While you were still
dating Julian here,
you were having fantasies
about someone else?
I'd rather not discuss it now.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
You brought it up.
You might as well
tell me who it is.
Yes, do tell.
( sighs )
It's...
Me?
Your brother...
Rom.
My brother Rom?
His brother Rom?
He's so cute...
and very sexy.
"Cute"?
"Sexy"?
Rom?
Here.
You need this
more than I do.
ARANDIS:
Just close your eyes
and watch your body.
Let all the tension drain away.
Doesn't the clay feel good?
Wonderful.
Now pour your emotions
into it.
Begin to mold it.
Feel the texture
in your hands.
I do.
I feel it.
I really do.
I knew you'd get it.
Dax.
Worf!
Worf?
I'm tired of giving speeches.
It's time we took action.
We've taken action--
the raid on the solarium.
It'll be forgotten
by tomorrow.
( door opens )
Mr. Worf?
You want to make
people leave Risa...
I think I know a way.
I probably would have reacted
the same way Worf did.
I mean, I know Arandis is
Curzon's lover, not yours
but if I'd walked in on the two
of you together, well...
trying to figure you out
at any given time isn't easy.
I like that
about her.
So do I.
It's the reason why I
chased after her so long.
Would you two please
stop talking about me
like I'm not here?
It's also the reason why I
stopped chasing after her.
You're too much work.
Worf is the one
who's too much work.
What you need is a Ferengi.
Maybe,
but what I want is Worf.
Why?
Because he has the courage
of a berserker cat,
and he has the heart of a poet.
And the brain
of a pigheaded idiot.
Yeah, sometimes.
Jadzia.
Any luck?
I'm afraid not.
None of the staff
can find him,
but I'm sure
he'll turn up.
Well, no sense
waiting around here for him.
I say we take some floaters
up into the hills
and go skinny-dipping
in the hot springs.
I never thought
I'd say this,
but I'm with Quark.
What was that?
Great. Just
what we needed.
I thought it wasn't
supposed to rain
in this part of Risa.
It's not.
Something must be wrong
with the weather grid.
( thunder rumbles )
May I have your
attention, please.
Obviously, the weather grid
is experiencing
some type of malfunction,
but I'm sure we'll be able
to repair it soon.
No...
you won't.
You're responsible
for this.
Oh, I authorized it,
but it was not my idea.
It was mine.
Are you serious?
He's serious.
Worf, what did you do,
build an uplink
so you could take control
of the weather grid?
The grid has been deactivated.
It will take three or four days
to restore the system
to normal operation.
During that time,
the inhabitants of Risa
and their guests will experience
the planet's
natural weather cycle.
And for most on Risa,
that means rain,
and plenty of it.
But why are you doing this?
Because Risa is an illusion
created
by weather control systems,
industrial replicators,
seismic regulators.
If the Federation
is going to survive,
we're going to have to stop
wasting our time with toys
and get back to the essentials.
I'm beginning to think
there's no hope for that man.
( thunder crashes )
Or for you, either, Mr. Worf.
Commander,
with all due respect,
are you out of your mind?
Oh, I think you will find me
quite rational.
As rational
as Klingons get, anyway.
Worf, this
is wrong.
I disagree.
If Federation citizens cannot
handle a little bad weather,
how will they handle
a Dominion invasion?
( thunder crashing,
wind whistling )
I have seen drier days
on Ferenginar
and we have 178
different words for rain.
Right now,
it's glebbening out there,
and that's bad.
If you're so miserable,
why don't you take
your Horga'hn
and go find some company?
Have you taken a good look
at the Risians lately?
They're even more depressed
than the guests.
I'm trying to organize
a game of hoverball.
Would either of you
like to join us?
In the rain?
No, on one of the indoor courts.
Indoor hoverball.
That's just wrong.
I'll play.
Good.
That makes one.
Having trouble
keeping the guests happy?
I've never heard
so much complaining in my life.
Nobody came here
to sit around in the rain.
It's not just
the weather.
People are starting
to complain about everything--
the rooms, the entertainment,
the food.
What's wrong with the food?
Nothing, as far as I can tell,
but the guests say
it just doesn't taste right.
It's the humidity.
It dampens the food,
makes everything mushy.
Trust me. There's no word
for "crisp" on Ferenginar.
Maybe Mr. Fullerton
was right.
Maybe we have forgotten
how to deal with adversity.
According to our figures,
the guest population
has declined by 30 percent
in the last three days.
And you can be sure
the guests that have stayed
are taking what you
have to say seriously.
It's a start.
One that you can build on.
You're leaving?
I have had my fill of Risa.
Mr. Worf, you've been
an inspiration to us all.
Good luck.
Thank you.
You still have the uplink
to the weather control grid?
Right here.
By tomorrow, the weather grid
will be restored to normal,
and no one here will remember
this ever happened.
But I intend to send a message
they won't forget.
You must be feeling
pretty good right now.
The weather's terrible,
the guests are miserable,
and more and more people
are leaving Risa every day.
Their response only
proves my point.
Oh, I see.
Ruin the vacations
of a few hundred thousand people
to bolster the moral fiber
of the Federation.
I do not expect you
to understand.
I understand...
even better than you do.
What you did had nothing
to do with Risa
or the Essentialists,
or even the Federation.
It's about you and me.
You give yourself
far too much credit.
Do I?
You think I'm irresponsible,
frivolous...
that I care more
about pleasure
than I do commitment.
What do you think is going on
between me and Arandis?
You know what I think.
That's right.
I do.
And you know what?
You're wrong.
Did it occur to you
to ask me about it?
Or... trust, just a little?
A Klingon woman would not have
given me grounds for suspicion.
And how would you know?
Curzon spent more time
with Klingons than you ever did.
You may have lived
among my people,
but you are not a Klingon.
I am.
Maybe so,
but you're not like
any Klingon I've ever met.
( sighs )
What happened to you, Worf?
You're a paragon
of Klingon honor and discipline,
but when it comes
to the Klingon
passion for life,
the exuberance,
the enjoyment of the moment,
you are constantly
holding yourself back.
Why?
That is not the issue here.
I think it is.
I do not wish
to lose you, Jadzia.
Then talk to me, please.
You know from the age of seven,
I was raised by humans
on the farm world of Gault.
It was a sparsely
populated world,
no more than 20,000 inhabitants.
It often seemed as though
everyone knew everybody else,
but one thing was for certain.
Everybody knew me.
I was the Klingon child,
the uncontrollable one.
I was the biggest,
the strongest,
the most fearless child
on the entire planet.
I fought hard, played hard,
did as I pleased.
What changed?
When I was 13, I was captain
of my school soccer team.
We had made the championships,
and I was determined to win.
Near the end of the second half
with the score tied,
my team got
a corner kick.
The ball
sailed up high.
Both I and one of my opponents,
a human boy named Mikel,
leapt up to head the ball.
He had position,
but I was determined to score.
I remember laughing
with excitement
as I threw myself at him.
Go on.
( sighing )
The next thing I knew,
the ball was sailing
into their goal.
I roared with triumph
and turned around to Mikel
to gloat,
only to find him lying
in the grass bleeding.
Our heads
had collided
when we both went up
for the ball.
I had not felt the impact,
but I had broken his neck,
and...
he died the next day.
It was an accident.
Which only makes it worse.
Compared to Klingons,
humans are fragile creatures.
I realized at that moment
to live among them,
I must practice restraint.
That must have been
difficult for you.
At first.
In time, it became a part
of who I was--
who... I am.
And you're still afraid
that if you lose control...
Someone I care about
might get hurt.
That explains a lot...
but you have to realize
there are some things
in life you can't control,
and one of them is me.
But what you can do is trust me.
I care about
you, Worf,
and I would never do
anything to hurt you.
Nor would I do
Who knows?
I may have more self-control
than you give me credit for.
( objects clattering )
That felt like
an earthquake.
( rumbling )
So did that.
The Essentialists.
You should see them all run.
I think they finally realized
that the party's over.
Increase the feedback
in the tectonic
stress regulators.
If I do, there won't be
a building left standing
on this part of Risa.
It might be
a good idea
to head to
the spaceport.
Or at least get
out of this room.
Very well.
I think our work
is done here.
WORF:
The uplink--
give it to me.
Mr. Worf, I suggest
you all get off this planet
as soon as possible.
I have no wish to see you
or your
friends harmed.
Give us the uplink,
or the only person
who will be harmed is you.
I thought you were
one of us.
Perhaps I was for a
time, but I believe
the Federation will survive
the Dominion, the Borg,
and people like you.
Mr. Worf...
if you walk out of here now,
you'll be turning your back
on the Federation.
Don't you see?
Overindulgence,
lack of self-control--
they'll destroy
everything we hold dear,
and you will be responsible.
You say that we have to return
to traditional
Federation values.
Well, I agree,
but one of those
values is trust.
It is essential that
we remember that.
Don't you walk away from me.
I will do as I please.
( groaning )
I am on vacation.
Figures-- the weather
improves the day we leave.
I can't wait
to get home.
Not that I didn't
enjoy myself.
I'd better
go find Bashir.
He brought a Horga'hn
down to breakfast,
and that's the last
I saw of him.
I hope the two of you
enjoyed Risa
and will come again.
I did not think that
I would be welcome.
Well, you still have
a lot to learn
about our people.
I never got a chance
to say good-bye to Curzon Dax.
And you're not saying
good-bye to me either.
I'll be back.
And Risa will be waiting.
So, what do we do now?
Now we watch
the suns set.
I have a better idea.
Why don't we go swimming?
I... didn't bring
a bathing suit.
I won't tell if you don't.