If I'd known
what I was walking into,
I never would have gone.
It was your idea
to attend the conference
in the first
place, Garak.
I thought the Bajorans
would be grateful
to hear someone
provide them
with an opposing
philosophical view.
Opposing view?
Garak, you were trying
to defend the military
occupation of their world.
How grateful did you think
they would be?
My understanding
of this conference was
that it was supposed to be
an examination of the occupation
from a dispassionate,
historical perspective.
Instead, everyone went
out of their way
to dismiss virtually everything
I had to say.
I thought the Bajorans
bent over backwards
to be polite to you, Garak.
Giving me a name tag that read
"Elim Garak--
Former Cardassian Oppressor"
was hardly polite.
And what did you want it to say?
"Former Spy"?
What I would have liked
was less posturing
and more debate.
It's clear to me now
that the Bajorans
aren't really interested
in discovering
historical truth
as much as they are in promoting
the myths and legends
of the "glorious resistance."
Well, Odo wasn't a member
of the resistance,
and he managed to attract
a fair amount
of attention.
Yes.
It seems you have
quite a fan club on Bajor.
I half-expected you
to be signing
autographs at the end.
Don't let him get to you, Odo.
You should be proud
of what you did
during the occupation.
I've nothing to be proud of.
I tried to bring order
to a chaotic situation.
That's all.
You need to give yourself
more credit, Constable.
Keeping order
during the occupation
would be a tough job for anyone,
but you not only did it,
you did it by earning
the trust of both sides.
DAX:
What was it
the moderator said?
That "you may have worked
for the Cardassians,
but your only master...
was justice."
And a legend is born.
Sir? Captain Sisko's runabout
is approaching the station.
Very well.
Clear them for docking
on Landing Pad 1.
Aye, sir.
Commander,
something's wrong.
They're not responding--
and sensors show
unusual EM signatures
along their hull.
The runabout's
on autopilot.
Life signs?
Four.
Very weak.
Disengage the autopilot.
Bring the runabout
to within transporter range.
Doctor Bashir
to Transporter Room 5.
Medical emergency.
WORF:
Check the aft compartment.
He's alive, but there's
an excess of neural energy
in his cerebral cortex.
What does that mean?
I'm not sure of that.
Can you revive them?
I'm not sure
of that, either.
( low hum of machinery )
( murmur of voices )
MALE ( over PA ):
All prisoners
return to your quarters.
( sighs )
Show some dignity.
Look at you.
No wonder the Cardassians
think we're animals.
Get up.
Get up!
If you're going to spend
the night taking chemicals,
stay off the Promenade.
We don't need
another cleansing today.
What happened?
Not here.
I couldn't agree more.
MALE ( over PA ):
All bio-organic material
must be disposed of
according to regulations.
( tricorder beeping )
There's a high level
of neural activity,
which suggests
that their conscious minds
are still active,
and yet, there's no response
to external stimuli.
What's the word on the runabout?
We have found
preliminary indications
that the ship encountered
a class-2 plasma storm,
which irradiated the vessel.
Computer,
are the neural readings
for subjects Odo, Sisko,
Dax, and Garak
consistent with the effects
of encountering
a class-2 plasma storm?
COMPUTER:
There are no recorded
causal relationships
between plasma storms
and specified neural readings.
BASHIR: None.
Computer, how many
medical records are there
on space plasma phenomena?
COMPUTER:
Five thousand twenty-one.
Well, it would appear
that a common phenomena
has had an uncommon
effect on our people.
Well, the runabout
is still being analyzed.
We should have
more information soon.
Good. In the meantime,
I have some reading to do.
This is Terok Nor--
DS9 during
the occupation.
Time travel?
Uh, no, it's
more than that.
Our clothes
have changed.
Could we be
in a holosuite?
Computer, end program.
Let's assume that's
a "no" for the moment.
Benjamin, we're not
attracting any attention.
And we should be.
Humans, Trills, and changelings
didn't just stroll
through Terok Nor unnoticed.
Well, then I should be getting
some attention as well.
We are
in the Bajoran sector,
and Cardassians
weren't exactly welcome here.
I don't think they see you
as a Cardassian.
I'm beginning to think
they don't see any of us
as who we really are.
The clothes we're wearing
are Bajoran.
They're treating us
like Bajorans.
Maybe they see us as Bajorans.
Any theories, old man?
Some kind
of cross-dimensional transfer?
Our conscious minds
might have been moved
through time and space
into the bodies
of four Bajorans on Terok Nor.
But then why are we still
seeing each other
as we really are,
instead of as Bajorans?
I just ran out of speculation.
The last thing I remember
was sitting in the runabout.
There was a plasma anomaly
on the sensors,
and then there was this sound.
No, not a sound.
More like
a strong vibration.
Hmm. I remember.
Odo?
I don't recall.
But whatever's happened,
we have to leave this place--
get off the station.
Then I suggest we go
directly to the authorities
and explain
our situation.
Garak.
I have knowledge
of certain... security codes
that would be sufficient
to prove that I am,
in fact, a Cardassian, even
if their eyes say otherwise.
I could always say that I'm
an undercover operative
posing as a Bajoran--
Captain, the authorities
on Terok Nor
will not be looking
for reasons to help us.
They will be looking
for a reason to interrogate us,
and believe me, you do not want
to be interrogated
by the Cardassians.
I tend to agree
with the Constable.
If they should discover
that we are actually
from the future...
Gul Dukat's
on the second level.
Let's move on.
( gasps )
SISKO:
Odo?
( gasps )
Who was that?
I don't know.
Well, you should.
It was your predecessor.
My predecessor?!
Oh... yes.
The man talking to Dukat.
His name is Thrax.
He was in charge of security
on the Promenade before me.
That means
we've gone back
at least
nine years.
You.
Come with us.
What's she done?!
Nothing... yet.
Perhaps there's been
some misunderstanding.
If I may be so bold,
you may find something
which will
bring you infinitely
more profit
than the arrest
of a Bajoran woman.
Latinum?
Two strips.
Where is it?
Ah, but our friend is
still in your custody.
Don't move!
( groaning )
Tempting offer.
Maybe next time.
This one's been selected.
I'll be all right.
Ooh.
Doctor.
Garak's septial capillaries
burst at this point.
The pattern
of his delta waves
show some unusual activity
at the same moment.
The bleeding
might be the result
of some kind
of psychosomatic response.
You mean, he thought
he was injured.
Well, under
certain conditions,
people have been known
to alter their blood pressure,
lower their
body temperature--
even manifest a tumor
as a result
of psychological stimuli.
Could these stimuli
cause more serious injuries?
I don't think he could
spontaneously break a bone,
but he could certainly
stop his heart
or break a key blood vessel
in his brain.
But what is causing all of this?
At the risk
of repeating myself,
I just don't know.
Step back from the gate.
He said,
"She's been selected."
What the hell does that mean?
Random interrogation,
forced labor relocation--
it could be anything.
That's not good enough.
I want to know
where they've taken her.
But before we can
help Commander Dax,
we need to find out who
we are in this reality.
If we could get
to a computer terminal,
we could ask
for a simple ID scan.
Computer access was extremely
limited on Terok Nor.
What about
a Cardassian comp-link?
Ha.
I took the liberty
of borrowing this
from the gentlemen
who thought my nose
needed adjustment.
I see I'm going to have
to add the word "pickpocket"
to your resume.
It's only a hobby.
Interesting
that a simple tailor
should just happen
to have
a high-level security code.
Yes, isn't it?
And if my nose
didn't hurt so much,
I'd tell you
a fascinating story
about how I came
to possess it.
Ah, yes.
Captain, you are actually
a Bajoran electronics engineer.
You're 38 years old,
you have no criminal record,
your family resides
in Rakantha Province,
and your name is Ishan Chaye.
Hmm. Lucky me.
I'm an artist.
I'm 55,
I've been arrested
three times
for disturbing the peace--
I must be incorrigible.
I also reside in Rakantha,
and my name is
Jillur Gueta.
And the Constable?
Ah, yes.
His profession is...
I'm a
bookkeeper.
46 years old.
I have a wife
and two sons
in Rakantha Province,
and my name is Timor Landi.
That's right.
How'd you know that?
Odo?
QUARK:
Congratulations, gentlemen.
You get to work today...
and you'll be laboring
in the finest establishment
on the station...
my establishment.
12 hours of work,
two five-minute
breaks--
one slip of latinum each.
Let's go.
Didn't you hear me?
I'm offering you work.
What are you waiting for?
N-nothing.
Just show us the way.
Open it.
Start by stepping
through the gate
that the nice man
has opened for you.
Very good.
You three must be
warp engineers.
Now, we're going
to walk down the Promenade
to the bar.
Would you like me
to hold your hands,
or can you manage it?
We'll manage.
I'm so glad.
How much damage would it do
to the timeline
if Quark were to suffer
a mysterious... accident?
I'm not sure,
but maybe
we should conduct
a little experiment
and find out.
Name?
Leeta.
Look at me when I speak
to you, Leeta.
She'll do.
Kanar.
For two.
( sighs )
Have you ever had kanar?
No.
Well, then this is an occasion.
You're trembling.
( sighs )
Despite what you
may have heard,
I'm a fair man, Leeta.
Rest assured
you have nothing to fear
from me.
I did not bring you here
to be abused.
Then why am I here?
It may surprise you
to hear this,
but my position is a lonely one.
I'm isolated from the people
who live under my protection.
I require someone...
to talk with.
In short...
a friend.
You want me to be your friend?
Ironic, isn't it?
That I should choose
a simple Bajoran girl
to share
my inner thoughts with.
But as you get to know me,
Leeta...
I think you'll find
that I'm a...
complicated man.
You're different
than I imagined.
To the beginning
of your education.
( clinking glasses )
I never knew
we were such messy conquerors.
I remember the occupation
being a little more tidy
than this.
Everything is tidy
when someone else
is doing the cleaning.
The Bajorans
were much more suited
for this sort of thing
than we were.
Servile work is in their nature.
I'll remember to mention that
to Major Kira when we get back.
There are exceptions
to every rule.
( tray rattling )
You all right?
The smell is making me sick.
Oh.
How did you know
your name would be Timor Landi
in this...
this whatever this is.
I recognized the other two names
from the security files
kept during the occupation.
Timor, Ishan, and Jillur
were the names of three Bajorans
who were accused of attempting
to assassinate
Gul Dukat
on the Promenade.
Half the resistance
tried to kill Dukat.
These three were innocent.
However, no one knew that
at the time,
and Dukat wanted
to make an example of them.
So he had them led
out onto the Promenade
and publicly... executed.
If we're them...
If we're them,
we better find a way out of here
before Dukat makes an example
out of us.
Quark,
I understand
you had a visit
from a Talavian freighter
captain this morning--
a Captain Livara,
I believe.
I had a lot of visitors
this morning.
It was a busy day.
I'm surprised
you're being so indiscreet.
Captain Livara
is a known smuggler.
You don't say?
Such a nice, friendly man, too.
I guess you never can tell
what some people
are really like.
Rumor has it that
the Obsidian Order has had him
under surveillance
for several months.
The Obsidian Order?
Rumor also has it
that they're bringing in
all of Livara's
coconspirators for...
questioning.
Well, you know how rumors are.
Yes.
They're usually true.
So, when the Order
asks me for a list
of all of Livara's
known associates
on board the station...
He was here
for ten minutes.
He wanted
to unload a shipment
of maraji crystals,
but I wasn't interested.
( scoffs )
I can't move
maraji crystals.
The Cardassians don't like them,
and the Bajorans
can't afford them,
so I sent him
on his way.
All right?
And that's all?
That's all.
I hope so...
because if I find out
that you've been dealing
in illegal crystals,
I'll hand you over
to the Order myself.
Always a pleasure.
I see you're not
the first man around here
to keep Quark
on his toes.
Yes.
Something's wrong.
Thrax talked about
a Captain Livara.
Does that name
mean something to you?
Livara wasn't just
another smuggler.
He was a Romulan spy
and didn't begin
working in this sector
until seven years ago,
but seven years ago,
Thrax wasn't on Terok Nor.
You were, Odo.
An odd contradiction.
So I checked the date.
This is seven years ago.
Thrax shouldn't be here.
You should be
the Security Chief.
None of this
makes any sense, Garak.
Now, I suggest we concentrate
on finding a way out of here.
That's our priority.
I tend to agree.
Well, you'll get
no argument from me...
but how?
We need to contact
the Bajoran resistance.
They might be able
to get us off the station.
Maybe even to the Federation.
Kira once told me
about a prearranged signal
the resistance used on Terok Nor
to set up a meeting.
Once we're finished here,
we'll head back
to the Bajoran sector,
and I'll make the signal.
Ah.
MALE ( on PA ):
All recreation passes
are suspended
for Alpha unit personnel
until further notice.
The Bajorans never did
have a sense of style.
Turn the vase over
and the resistance
appears.
It's simple and effective.
And they did it
for years
right under
the Cardassians' noses.
Not under my nose, Captain.
Under his.
At least Dax is all right.
Look at him.
( scoffs ):
The Commander of Terok Nor.
Just another swaggering,
self-important Gul
with too much vanity
and not enough ability.
Maybe, but he's no fool.
Uh!
( gasping )
Are you all right?
Yes.
Just slipped out of my hand.
You wanted a meeting?
Don't look at me.
Eat your soup.
I didn't think you would come
while Dukat was here.
Everyone's watching
our gentle dictator
stroll the Promenade
with his new girlfriend.
Now, I hate soup,
and I have no intention
of finishing this entire bowl,
so whatever you want,
let's hear it.
We need to get off the station.
Why?
Does it matter?
Yes, as a matter of fact,
it does.
We're not a commuter service.
If you're running from a dispute
over chemicals
or women or smuggling,
you're on your own.
If you've killed
one of the spoon heads...
Spoon heads?!
Garak!
That's a different matter.
We're not who we seem to be.
I hope not, because you seem
to be wasting my time.
Let's just say we're involved
with the Federation.
Let me guess.
You're Starfleet agents
operating undercover
posing as indigent Bajorans
who happen to be...
( explosion )
( alarm blares )
Dax!
No, no!
Captain! No!
PA:
Secure all exits on 4-Alpha.
Captain, w-we
can't stay here.
They'll take
care of her...
CARDASSIAN:
You two, halt!
But we must go!
CARDASSIAN:
Grab him!
Don't move!
( people clamoring, pounding)
You'd think they'd put us
in our own cell block
instead of with
the common criminals.
After all, we are
accused of attempting
to assassinate the
Station Commander.
That deserves
some respect.
Maybe they'll salute
when they execute us.
( clamor intensifies )
Quiet down.
Quiet.
Quiet, please.
Quiet, please!
( shouting stops )
Kara Polus...
Brin Tusk...
and Marat Kobar...
your sentence
is five years hard labor.
Trial to confirm
this sentence
will be held
at 1700 hours.
Benten Vek.
Your fine has been paid,
and you'll be free to go
within the hour.
Lobo, Horis, Romara,
Pelin, and Gramm.
You are being transferred
to Cardassian authorities
on Bajor for interrogation.
No, no please...
Timor, Ishan, Jillur.
You came aboard this station
two days ago
from the Rakantha Province.
Yesterday, you paid a visit
to the chemist's shop
and then fell asleep
on the Promenade.
Last night, you were hired
as a cleanup crew
by the Ferengi.
And after you were paid,
you went back
to the Bajoran sector
and attempted to murder
Gul Dukat
with a chambered plasma grenade.
We were sitting
at a table eating
when the grenade went off.
There were witnesses.
None of which have come forth.
Why would the witnesses
risk their lives
for three strangers?
They're out there,
but you have to go
look for them.
THRAX:
Epidermal scans
revealed the presence
of trinitrogen chloride
on your hands and clothing.
TNC is one of the components
in plasma grenades.
TNC is also
a cleaning solution,
which is what we were
using in Quark's.
Or you used
the opportunity
of working at Quark's
to obtain the TNC
in the first place.
You all have ties
to the Bajoran underground.
You have three cousins
who are known members
of the resistance.
Five of your friends
are suspected sympathizers.
ODO:
After 50 years
of occupation,
is there anyone
left on Bajor
who doesn't have some tie
to the resistance?
Quiet!
( clamor ceases briefly )
That may be true,
but you were seen
rushing toward Dukat
after the explosion.
Everyone else was running away.
I wanted to help my friend.
She was injured
in the blast.
The report of the Cardassian
guards states
that you were found
over the body of Gul Dukat
attempting to strangle him.
That's a lie.
Interrogate
the troops yourself.
Don't just take their report
at face value.
I don't interrogate members
of the Cardassian military.
Then run a ballistic analysis
of the explosion.
If you examine the fragmentation
dispersal pattern,
you'll find that we couldn't
have thrown the grenade
from our position at the table.
It had to have
come from...
Quiet!
Quiet down!
There is sufficient evidence
for a conviction.
All of which is circumstantial.
Go beneath the surface.
Conduct a real investigation.
This investigation is over.
Your case
is going before
a special tribunal
this afternoon.
You will be informed
of the sentence
just before it meets.
No! Wait!
I need to talk to you!
Let me talk to you alone
for just a moment!
Please! Listen to me!
That's enough.
How do you feel?
Better than the last time.
Last time?
This is the fourth
assassination attempt
I've survived.
Maybe you should find
another job.
( laughing )
Maybe I should.
I'm glad to see you
have your appetite back.
I don't get to eat
like this very often.
I've wanted
to increase rations
in the Bajoran sector
for some time now.
But the resistance
makes it almost impossible
to show any sort of
kindness to your people.
You really want to help
my people, don't you?
Yes, of course.
The Bajorans are...
well, they're like
my children, I suppose,
and like any father,
I want only what's
best for them.
And you still feel that way now
after some of your children
have tried to kill you?
Bad manners are the
fault of the parent,
not the child.
My weakness is I'm too...
generous...
too forgiving.
My heart is too big.
( groans )
And so is your ego.
"Yes, I know I don't
look Cardassian.
"You see, I was
surgically altered
to appear Bajoran."
But what if genetic scans
show no Cardassian DNA
in my cellular structure?
In that case,
I'll suggest--
Tell me about Thrax.
What do you want to know?
Something about his background.
He seems unusual.
Doesn't have
that casual brutality
I've come to expect
from Cardassian
security officers.
What makes Thrax different?
I wouldn't know.
He was gone by the time
I came aboard the station.
Which brings up a good point.
Why is he here now?
Garak said that you
were the Security Chief
during this time.
You're implying that I
should know the answers--
that I'm holding
back information?
I'm saying that maybe you know
more than you think you do.
You lived here, on Terok Nor.
You're supposed to be out there
now instead of Thrax.
Think, Odo.
There might be some connection
between you and what's
happening here.
I don't know.
( high-pitched squeal )
Miss me?
DAX:
Dukat's personal shuttle
is in Docking Bay 3.
What about the station
defense system?
I've got the computer
tied up in knots.
I don't think
they'll be able--
Halt!
( groans )
( grunting )
GARAK:
A changeling?
We'll figure that out later.
Here it is.
We just got the word.
Your execution's
been scheduled for 1900.
That's two hours from now.
We've got to find
another way out of here.
We tried that.
Escape doesn't seem
to be the answer.
How could Thrax
be a changeling?
In this time period,
the Founders didn't know
about the wormhole.
I don't know.
GARAK:
Well, putting aside
the newest
shape-shifter in town
for the time being,
how did we end up
back in this cell?
I don't know.
Care to guess?
What makes you think
I have the answer?
You've been
acting strangely
ever since we first woke up
on the Promenade.
Continually distracted,
depressed, and agitated.
And you knew
the names
of the people we're
supposed to be.
You knew the details
of the case
like you were there.
But you couldn't
have been there
because it happened
before you came
aboard the station.
Everything seems
to lead back to you,
and I want
to know why.
THRAX:
You said you wanted
to see me?
Yes. It's urgent.
I'm listening,
but I don't have much time.
You are about to make
a very serious mistake.
Because you're innocent,
of course.
All of you.
That's right,
and I can prove it.
Compare this attack to
recent bombings on Bajor.
You'll find a similarity
to four incidents
in Musilla Province,
none of which
we could have done.
This proves nothing.
And under Cardassian law,
the accused
must prove his innocence.
Since the evidence in this case
is sufficient
to warrant conviction,
the investigation is over.
Your job is to find the truth,
not obtain convictions.
Truth.
You want the truth?
All right, the truth is
that none of you
would be accused--
none of you would even be here--
if the Bajorans weren't fighting
the Cardassians.
It's futile.
The occupation
has lasted for 50 years,
and it will probably last
another 50.
I wouldn't be too
sure about that.
Why not just accept it?!
If the Bajoran people would
accept their place in history,
none of this would be happening.
We are talking about
the attempt on Gul Dukat's life,
not the socio-political
ramifications of the resistance.
It's all part
of the same problem!
When your people resort
to terrorism and violence,
they're fighting against order,
against stability,
against the rule of law--
and this must be stopped.
There is more to life
than the rule of law.
It has been my observation
that only the guilty
make that kind of statement.
( groaning )
I didn't want to tell you this--
I don't know what
the consequences will be--
but we are not terrorists.
We're not even Bajorans.
There's been a temporal
displacement of some kind.
We don't belong in this time.
We're from the future.
I know.
You know?
Then what are you going
to do about it?
What I am supposed to do.
Nothing more, nothing less.
The question is:
What are you going to do...
Odo?
( gasps )
THRAX:
It's too late for them now.
It's out of my hands.
Why aren't I with them?
There were only
three terrorists, Odo.
You know that.
This is the price
for taking up arms
against those who
would protect you...
who have only your best
interests at heart.
They haven't done anything.
They don't belong here.
It's already
happened, Odo.
But this isn't what happened.
It wasn't these people.
Proceed
with the execution.
ODO:
No.
I'm not going to let this
happen again.
Not again!
( grunting )
You can't execute them.
You don't even belong here.
I do.
( disrupter firing )
Constable?
That's exactly how it happened
seven years ago.
It was you all along.
Yes.
I was Chief of Security
on the Promenade.
I was the one
who charged those men
with a crime
they didn't commit,
and I was the one
who turned them over
to Dukat.
Three days after the executions,
there was another bombing
on the Promenade
identical to the one
that almost killed Dukat.
Timor, Ishan, and Jillur
were innocent.
All the evidence
was there--
the inconsistencies
in the reports
of the soldiers
who arrested them,
a pattern of bombings,
the ballistics--
it was all there
from the beginning.
But I was too busy,
too concerned
with maintaining order
and the rule of law.
I thought of myself
as the outsider,
the shape-shifter
who cared for nothing
but justice.
It never occurred
to me that I
could fail, but I did,
and I never wanted anyone
to know the truth--
that seven years ago,
I allowed three innocent men
to die.
( ragged breathing )
BASHIR:
Constable?
( gasps )
Whatever it is
you've been through
has taken its toll.
Far as I can tell,
the four of you were locked
into some version
of the Great Link.
The Link?
How is that possible?
I'm a solid now.
Well, it seems you're not
as solid as you think.
When I ran a neurochemical
scan of your brain,
I found residual traces
of morphogenic enzymes,
which I've only detected before
in changelings.
When the plasma storm
hit the runabout,
it activated the enzymes
and initiated
a telepathic response.
Your mind reached out
to find other changelings
to form the Link,
but all it could find
were Sisko, Dax, and Garak.
And just before the accident,
I was thinking
about the executions.
Somehow, being in the Link
must've forced me to relive it
and admit the truth
about what I'd done.
It would make
a fascinating paper.
Although,
I don't intend to write one.
If you have
any questions,
uh, you know where to find me.
( sighing )
When I first read your report...
I didn't know what to think.
So I said to myself,
"That's all right, Nerys.
"You're stunned.
You need to let it
sink in a little."
But it's been two days, Odo.
I still don't know
what to think.
I'm guilty.
What more is there to say?
Maybe nothing.
Maybe a lot.
I believed in you.
A lot of people did.
You were special.
You were the one man
who stood apart
from everyone else...
the one man who stood
for justice.
Now what?
Now I'm...
just another...
imperfect solid.
Okay.
The Prophets know
I'm not perfect.
I guess the truth is
that anyone who lived through
the occupation
had to get a little dirty.
But I need to know
that no other innocent people
died on your watch, Odo.
That this was the only time.
I'm not sure.
I hope so.