I am Vedek Latha Mabrin
and I welcome you
to the Calash Retreat.
Today, we begin prayer
and meditation
as preparation
for our Days of Atonement.
May the Prophets walk with us
as we begin our journey.
( groans )
Have you been taking
your makara herbs?
Absolutely.
( clears throat )
Mostly.
Kira, you have
to take them.
Your progesterone levels
are way too low.
But if I take the herbs
then the sedatives
you gave me don't work.
The herbs do act
as a counteragent.
But I thought you said
you weren't having
any trouble sleeping
and that you didn't
need any sedatives.
I don't.
But, Julian,
those herbs taste
like something that crawled
out of Quark's ear.
Just take them.
All right.
ODO:
Major, may I have
a word with you?
We're finished here.
Sure.
I'm afraid I have
some very bad news.
One of the former members
of your resistance cell
has been killed on Bajor.
Latha Mabrin.
How?
It appears a small
hunter probe
was hidden inside
a ceremonial candle
and fired a disrupter blast.
Do they have any suspects?
Too many.
Before he became a vedek
your friend was involved in some
very questionable activities.
Latha was a violent man
but then he found the Prophets.
And the last time
I talked to him,
he'd changed-- really changed.
I don't doubt that, Major,
but it would appear
that the violence of his past
has finally caught up with him.
Let me know
if you hear anything else.
Of course.
COMPUTER:
Major Kira
there is one message
waiting for you.
( sighs )
Play back message.
( scrambled voice ):
That's one.
Replay audio.
Again.
That's one.
( scrambled voice ):
As you might have guessed,
there's no point of origin
listed in the computer log.
When did we receive
this message?
It came over the primary
subspace antenna
at 1341 hours--
almost the same moment
Latha was killed on Bajor.
And you think
that this is a threat
to all the former members
of the Shakaar
resistance cell?
That's my working theory,
but I'm not ruling anything out.
Did anyone else
receive this message?
Not that we know of.
So obviously there's
some connection to me
but I don't know what it is.
I haven't even spoken
to Latha in two years.
I'm waiting for the preliminary
crime scene report
from the authorities on Bajor
before I begin
my own investigation,
but I'd like to increase
security here on the station
and initiate random checks
on all
incoming cargo.
Agreed.
I've contacted most
of the surviving members
of the Shakaar--
warned them to take
precautions just in case.
I'm sorry
about your friend.
He died serving the Prophets.
They'll take care of him.
I'm sure they will.
Keep me informed.
How you feeling?
Fine.
Exhausted.
I didn't get much sleep
and Julian's got me back
on those herbs again.
I know.
I heard you pacing all night.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I would have gotten up
and kept you company
but I figured you wanted
to be alone.
I couldn't stop thinking
about Latha.
All those firefights and bombs
he lived through
just to be killed
during a religious ceremony.
You know, if I wasn't pregnant,
I would be down on Bajor right
now trying to narrow down
the suspects.
You're safer on the station.
That's what's driving me crazy.
I'm sitting here
eating breakfast
while someone may be
hunting down my friends.
I'm a Major
in the Bajoran militia.
I should be down there
trying to protect them.
Right now, you're needed here,
protecting someone else.
Yeah, I...
guess I do have my hands full
at the moment.
ODO:
Ops to Major Kira.
Go ahead, Odo.
There's another incoming
message for you, Major,
and they refuse to give
either their name
or location.
I'm on my way.
We're having trouble
tracing the signal.
They're running it through
some kind of scrambler
using a phase-divergent
carrier wave.
Try to keep them talking.
This is Major Kira Nerys.
Who am I talking to?
Nerys?
Is that really you?
Fala?
Are you alone?
I don't want anyone to hear me.
I think...
I think someone's trying
to trace my signal.
Stand by.
She's a friend.
Her name is Trentin Fala.
One of the members
of your cell?
No.
Then why is
she hiding
her location?
I'd rather not
talk about it here
but trust me,
she's no threat to anyone.
Let me talk to her alone
and see what's going on.
I'm alone, and no one here
will trace your signal.
You heard about Latha?
They killed him.
As he knelt in prayer,
they killed him.
I know,
and the authorities
are investigating that
right now.
They're going
to kill me, too, Nerys.
They've been watching me.
Who's been watching you?
I don't know.
But I feel it.
I need to get out of here.
Go somewhere safe.
Please, Nerys,
you've got to help me.
You always promised you'd help.
All right, calm down.
I'll protect you.
You can stay here at the station
until all of this is over.
Okay.
Two of our officers
are returning
this afternoon from Starbase 63.
I'll reroute them to Bajor
and have them pick you up, okay?
Okay.
Their names are Worf
and Jadzia Dax.
They'll contact you
within the hour.
I knew I could count on you.
I'll see you soon.
You've been smirking ever since
we left the starbase.
I do not smirk.
But if I did, this would
be a good opportunity.
How was I supposed to know
that Captain Ramirez
was a three-time
tongo champion?
You might have asked
before mocking him
and then allowing him
to up the stakes
to a no-limit game.
I didn't lose that much.
Two bars of latinum.
I hope you have it.
I have it...
most of it.
Worf...?
No.
Fine.
I'll borrow it from Quark.
He likes me.
( console beeping )
Major Kira's friend is ready
for transport.
Quark may lend you
the money, but remember Rule
of Acquisition Number 111:
"Treat people
in your debt
like family-- exploit them."
You know the Rules
of Acquisition?
I'm a graduate
of Starfleet Academy.
I know many things.
Energizing.
There's a power surge
in the buffer.
Something is interfering
with the integration matrix.
I'm transferring
her pattern
to the secondary buffer.
Boost the gain
on the energizing coils.
It won't go any higher.
I'm losing her.
I'm sorry, Nerys.
I'm hearing that
a lot lately.
Can I have a moment?
Of course.
I wish there was something
I could say, Major.
Just tell me it
was an accident.
The Constable
thinks otherwise.
I believe she was killed
by a remat detonator.
It's a device
programmed to scramble
a transporter beam
during rematerialization.
They're typically
no more than two cubic
millimeters in size.
It could have been
hidden in her clothing
or injected
into her skin.
The device is typically used
by the Romulans.
However, it is sold
on the black market.
Why didn't the transporter
security system
detect the device?
DAX:
We're not sure.
The system is programmed
to scan for remats.
So whoever did this
has a sophisticated
understanding
of our security
protocols.
And a vendetta against
the Shakaar resistance cell.
I thought you said
that Trentin Fala wasn't
a member of the Shakaar.
She wasn't...
at least not officially.
Fala spent the occupation
cleaning floors
in a Cardassian records office
in Dakhur Province.
She passed us information
for years
without anyone catching on
but she was
always so afraid--
afraid she'd be caught
and executed...
but she never stopped.
I told her once
that I thought she was
braver than all of us
because she had to live
with her fear every day.
Even after
the occupation was over,
she didn't want
anyone to know
that she was
secretly helping us.
She was worried...
that someone would come looking
for her for revenge.
Looks like her fears
were well founded.
( scrambled voice ):
That's two.
Hello, Major.
I was just about to call you.
Quark, what is that?
I just found this padd
in a shipment of Saurian brandy
I just received.
It was coded for you
but somehow,
I accidentally activated it.
Give that to me.
That's two.
That's...
ODO:
Since she was an informant,
it stands to reason
that Fala was killed
because she was providing
information to the resistance--
information that the Shakaar
used to plan an attack
on a Cardassian target.
The killer is probably someone
who was either injured or who
lost a family member
or a friend
in that attack.
We planned dozens of attacks
based on Fala's information.
It could be any of them.
Not "any."
We're dealing
with an operation
in which you played
a prominent part.
Now, perhaps
you could make a list
of all the attacks
by the Shakaar
in which
you participated.
It's a long list.
( console beeping rapidly )
Someone is accessing
the security database.
Can you trace it?
No.
( scrambled voice ):
That's three.
Mobara.
He was in the Shakaar.
Where does Mobara live?
Um, Musilla province,
at the University...
Engineering School.
I'm sending an emergency message
to the authorities in Musilla.
Maybe it's not too late.
Are you all right?
No, I'm not all right!
I haven't slept in three days,
someone is killing my friends
and my back...
Sorry.
No apology necessary, Major.
( console beeping )
( sighs )
They haven't been able
to contact Mobara
so they're sending
a search party
to the University right now.
They'll let us know
what happens.
Major,
if I may make a suggestion--
why don't you return
to your quarters
and rest for now?
It may be several hours
before they're able
to make a complete search.
Maybe you're right.
But let me know
the moment you hear something.
You have my word.
( sighs )
I'm going to lie down.
Help yourself
to the replicator
if you're hungry.
Thank you, Major.
( sighs )
( thud )
( thumping )
( clatter )
Don't move!
Hold it.
Furel?
Nerys?
( sighs )
Oh! You're lucky
I didn't shoot you.
Well, I could say
the same about you.
What are you doing
creeping around
in a dark room with a phaser?
I live here.
What about him?
Oh... This is
Lieutenant Brilgar.
He's station security
here to protect me.
Oh. Sorry.
You know these people,
Major?
I'm afraid so.
This is Furel, Lupaza.
We were in the same
resistance cell.
Brilgar, sorry about the...
Yeah, yeah.
I'll be outside
if you need me.
Thank you.
How did you get in?
We just installed
a new security system.
And a pretty good one
it is, too.
But they have not yet
invented the system
that Lupaza cannot beat.
( laughs )
It took some work
but I managed to retune
the transporter scrambler.
You beamed in?
From where?
We stowed away
aboard a transport ship
making a run from Bajor.
Just before it docked,
I accessed the station
personnel records.
We beamed into the bedroom
about five minutes ago.
We heard
somebody moving around in here.
I thought it was you.
But it turned out to be
a man with a phaser--
FUREL:
And I tried
to tell her
that we should contact you
before we came--
You did not.
I should have you both
thrown in the brig...
but I'm glad to see you.
( chuckling )
It's good to see you.
( whispering ):
Go get it.
What? Oh...
Can I?
Oh.
How much longer?
A couple of weeks.
Been sneezing?
Off and on.
The doctor's
giving me something.
But before we get
too deep into baby talk
I had another
message today.
This time, it's Mobara.
Dead?
We don't
know yet.
There's a search party out
right now looking for him.
Do you have any suspects?
No.
Well, when
you do you let us know.
That's why
we're here--
to find out who's doing this...
and take care of it.
I can't send you out
like some assassination squad.
You don't have
to send us anywhere.
You just give us the name.
We'll take care of the rest.
The occupation is over.
We can't go around
fighting private wars.
Times have changed.
We have got
to change with it.
Leave this
for the authorities.
Authorities?!
Maybe you feel
that way now
but trust me
when you find out
who killed Latha and Fala
and maybe now Mobara,
you're not going to want
to leave it to someone else.
You're going to want him dead
and you're going
to want us to do it.
( sighs )
Maybe so,
but we're not at that point yet.
Hmm.
What's in the box?
It's for you.
For me?
A gift.
Makara herbs.
You're...
You're supposed to take them
during your pregnancy.
LUPAZA:
She knows
what they're for.
We thought
you might have trouble
getting fresh herbs
on the station
so we picked them last night.
Thanks.
Really... thank you.
Well, if you're staying,
I better find you some quarters.
We're staying right here
where we can keep
an eye on you...
on both of you.
Yeah, we'll sleep out here.
The couch is
a little short
but it's probably
as comfortable as our bed.
Well, since Keiko's visiting
her parents with Molly,
I guess there's room.
Hold it!
It's all right!
Miles...
we have houseguests.
ODO:
They found his body
about two hours ago...
or at least what was left of it.
Mobara had
a micro-explosive implanted
just behind
his right ear.
How could someone get
close enough
to implant something
behind someone's ear
and not get caught?
I doubt he was ever
near Mobara.
The killer's shown a pattern
of using remote control devices.
He was probably using some sort
of hunter probe
and injected Mobara as he slept.
What are we dealing with here--
a professional assassin?
Well, that was
my initial thought,
but a professional
would never be sending
anonymous messages.
No, our killer is someone
with a very personal
stake in this--
someone who is trying
to make a point
to Major Kira.
And once he drives
his point home?
He'll try
to kill her, too.
( scrambled voice ):
That's one.
That's two.
That's three.
It doesn't sound natural.
No kidding.
I mean, I know they're using
some kind of scrambler
to disguise the voice,
but there's
something else.
The rhythms don't
sound natural.
More like a composite of words
from different speeches
put together.
You can tell that
through all the distortion?
It's the lobes.
The intonation and phrasing
are slightly off.
I've made it a policy
never to argue
with someone's lobes.
KIRA:
All right
let's say these are
composite messages.
Does that help us?
Maybe.
Since the first word
of all three messages
is the same,
let's assume it's simply
been copied three times.
That gives me a reference
to begin screening out
the electronic interference.
That's... that's... that's...
that's...
NOG:
It's a female.
that's...
And it's not Cardassian.
You're sure?
Uh, all right.
All right.
...that's... that's...
It's... Bajoran.
I know that voice.
Can I hear the rest
of the words?
That's one.
That's two.
That's three...
It's me.
That's one...
He's using my voice.
( beeping )
There's been an explosion
in the Habitat Ring.
Location.
Level 5,
Section 21-Alpha.
The O'Brien's quarters.
Go to Red Alert.
Stop all incoming
and outgoing ships
until further notice.
NOG:
Aye, sir.
Dax to Infirmary.
Dr. Bashir report
to Habitat Ring Level 5
Section 21-Alpha--
medical emergency.
Report.
There's been
an explosion
in O'Brien's
quarters.
There's a hull breach.
The compartment is
venting air into space.
Casualties?
No word yet.
I'm having trouble
scanning through the debris.
Where's Kira?
MAN:
Major, you can't go in.
There's a hull breach--
Get out of my way!
Major, please...
Major, no.
You'll vent
the whole corridor.
( gasps )
( groaning )
Nerys?
Nerys, can you hear me?
Julian...
You're in the Infirmary.
( gasps ):
The baby...?
He's fine.
You suffered
a placental laceration
and then you began
to hemorrhage
but I've repaired
the damage.
You're going
to be all right.
( groans )
( sighs )
Lupaza and Furel...
they're dead,
aren't they?
I'm afraid so.
Miles?
He wasn't there
when it happened.
Did they die quickly?
Instantly.
ODO:
Doctor, may I?
BASHIR:
I'll be right outside.
I was 13 when I joined
the resistance.
I'd been hanging around
the Shakaar base camp
for a couple of weeks--
you know, running errands
cleaning weapons,
that kind of thing.
Then one night, they
had an ambush planned
and they were a man short,
so I volunteered
but everyone thought
I was too young, too small.
Lupaza stuck up for me.
She said I had
the heart of sinoraptor
and they didn't have
much choice.
Furel made some kind of joke.
I don't remember what it was
but I do remember
that Lupaza hit him.
She was always doing that.
They loved each other
in some way.
But it was up to Shakaar,
and he stared at me
for a long time
before he decided
I was big enough
to carry a phaser rifle
after all.
So we set the ambush up
along a ridgeline that night
and waited.
I was so cold.
My hands were shaking.
I was so afraid that one of them
would look at me
and think that I was nervous
that I kept biting my fingers
to keep the blood flowing.
We must have
waited there
three or four hours
before the
skimmer appeared.
It set down
right where Furel
said it would.
And when that hatch opened
and that first Cardassian
appeared,
I just started firing
and I didn't stop
'till I'd discharged
the entire power cell.
When it was all over, I...
I was so relieved
that I hadn't let anyone down
I, I was giddy.
Furel told me to stop grinning,
that it made me look younger,
but I couldn't help it.
I was one of them.
I was in the resistance.
Lupaza made me this...
out of some of the metal
from that skimmer.
How were they killed?
Someone attached
a small hunter probe
to the hull
of a Talavian freighter.
When the ship docked
at the station,
the probe detached itself
and then began a visual scan
of every room
in the Habitat Ring.
Once the probe found
its assigned targets,
it attached itself to the window
and exploded.
Do you have any leads?
My sources on Cardassia
have given me a list
of possible suspects.
They all have
the computer skills
the opportunity, and the motive
to carry out
these attacks.
You must have called in
a lot of favors.
One or two.
How many people
are on the list now?
Twenty-five.
Can I see it?
Not... just yet.
I'd like to...
narrow it a little.
You're afraid I'm going
to take the names
and go charging off after them.
Something like that.
( laughing )
You're right.
I probably would.
I'm going to find
the person that's done this.
I promise you that.
I know you will, Odo.
Keep me informed.
Absolutely.
( panting )
COMPUTER:
Emergency transport
standing by.
Enter command code
authorization.
Authorization: Kira-
one-five-seven-alpha.
Initiating transport.
Computer, initiate emergency
transport program Kira-2.
Initiating transport.
Computer, locate Major Kira.
Major Kira is
no longer on the station.
( grunts )
ODO:
She's obviously going after
the suspects on the list
but she erased their names
from my computer file
when she got them,
so there's no way
to know where she's headed.
Prepare the Defiant.
I want to leave
in ten minutes
see if we can pick up
her ion trial.
It will be difficult.
Our sensor logs
show Major Kira
masked her engine emissions
with a polaron field.
The runabout's particle--
I know what the
difficulties are.
You have your orders.
Dismissed.
Aye, sir.
( sighing )
Kira Nerys, Personal Log,
Stardate 50416.2.
I've eliminated three of
the suspects from Odo's list.
I'm satisfied that none of them
could have committed
the murders.
The fourth name is Silaran Prin
a Cardassian living
on a planet near the DMZ.
MALE:
A creature, born within the
comforting anonymity of darkness
awakens in the harsh truth
of daylight.
It squirms in the glare,
afraid of the light
that pins it to the chair
like a needle through its heart.
Its heart beats faster...
Who's there?
Silaran, is that you?
Panic starts
to creep into its soul.
Does it understand?
Or is it so blinded
by the light
that it can think only
of returning
to the velvet cloak of darkness?
No matter.
Perhaps it is better
that it doesn't realize
how close death has come.
But make no mistake,
there is no escape.
It has reached the end
and soon it will die.
What's the matter, Silaran?
Are you so afraid
of a pregnant woman
in a restraining field
you have to hide in the dark?
It bears its tiny fangs,
hoping for a chance to strike--
to sink its teeth deep
into the flesh of its tormentor,
but that chance will never come.
You better hope
I don't get that chance.
And somewhere
beneath the gleam
of hatred in those eyes
lurks the certain knowledge
of its impending death,
and it begins
to know fear.
I'm not afraid of you.
I'm not some coward
who's been sending anonymous
messages and bombs
to murder innocent people.
No, Kira, I didn't
murder anyone!
You did.
You killed them all.
There.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Now we can talk.
Talk and lies
won't help you.
You're in the light,
and the light
reveals the truth.
And the light shows me no regret
in those eyes, no compassion.
You want me to...
feel compassion for you?
You murdered five people.
What compassion
did you show to them?
Unrepentant.
How unfortunate.
I thought you might
have changed...
might have found a path
out of the darkness.
What am I supposed
to feel repentant for?
What are you talking about?
That is part of your guilt.
You did this to me...
and you don't
even know
who... I... am.
So you were wounded
during an attack I carried out
when I was part
of the resistance
and I'm supposed to feel guilty?
We were at war, Silaran.
15 million Bajorans died
during the occupation
and you want me
to feel sorry for you?
No, I wasn't part
of your war.
I was an innocent.
I wasn't even
in the military.
Do you know what
I did on Bajor?
I was a servant.
I cleaned uniforms
for Gul Pirak.
Gul Pirak...
Commander of the weapons depot
at Hathon.
I'm glad that you remember.
Now, do you remember...
what you did?
How you put
a plasma charge
outside his bedroom window
in the middle of the night?
I remember.
He executed
15 Bajoran farmers because
they refused to display
the Cardassian banner
outside their homes.
Trentin Fala showed you
how to circumvent
the defense system.
Latha Mabrin built
the plasma charge.
Furel
and Lupaza stood
guard outside
while you crept up to the house.
None of us liked killing.
We were fighting
for our freedom against--
You vaporized
the entire east wing!
12 Cardassians were killed
including Gul Pirak's
entire family.
23 others
were crippled.
Don't you feel guilty?
Don't you feel ashamed
of what you did?
None of you belonged on Bajor.
It wasn't your world.
For 50 years,
you raped our planet
and you killed our people,
you lived on our land
and you took the food
out of our mouths
and I don't care whether you
held a phaser in your hand
or you ironed shirts
for a living.
You were all guilty, and you
were all legitimate targets!
That's what makes you
a murderer--
indiscriminate killing,
no sense of morality,
no thought given to
the consequences of your action.
That's what makes us different.
I was a soldier!
You're just a bitter old man
out for revenge.
I am bringing the guilty
to justice...
and unlike you, I take care
to protect the innocent.
I could have killed
every monk in that cavern
or everyone
on the runabout
or half the population
of Deep Space 9, but I didn't.
Only the guilty have died.
And that is why...
although your actions
have condemned you,
the life
of your child
will be spared.
What does that mean?
What does that mean?!
The creature's diseased mind
cannot understand its plight.
Its imagination
is too limited
to perceive the truth--
it cannot be saved.
But there is still hope
for the child.
It could be taken from the womb
and raised
in the light.
Listen to me, Silaran.
The child I'm carrying,
it isn't Bajoran--
it's human.
It has unique medical needs.
If you force me to give
birth now, you risk--
The creature's cries
grow louder
but no one can hear them.
All that remains is to bring
the child into the light
and discard the diseased
carcass of the mother
before it can infect
its offspring.
You can't bring it
into the light-- not yet!
Dr. Bashir said
if I don't have at least
three more weeks--
It's time.
We both agree
this baby is an innocent.
Don't put him at risk,
please, Silaran.
Don't worry.
I promise that I'll take care
of the child...
and that I'll teach him
the difference between darkness
and light.
Wait.
Please, I'm begging you.
At least give me a sedative.
Show some compassion.
Don't just cut me open.
All right.
I'll show more mercy
than you have.
( sighs )
Take a good look
at my face, Kira!
I want it to be
the last thing
you see.
The creature slept...
dreaming its dark dreams
and happy to be
out of the light.
The innocent life
it held
would awaken
in brilliance...
and never...
know darkness...
again.
Oh!
( grunts )
Are you all right?
She's fine
but there's a large amount
of merfadon in her system.
"Merfadon"?
It's a sedative.
But the makara herbs
she's been taking
have counteracted the effect.
I take it this is our assassin.
Why did he give you
a sedative?
He wanted
to protect the innocent...
and separate the darkness
from the light...
but he didn't realize...
the light
only shines
in the dark
and sometimes innocence is
just an excuse for the guilty.
Let's go home.
Sisko to Defiant.
Go ahead.
Four to beam up.
Energize.