Captain's Log, Stardate 50485.2.
I've come to Marva IV,
a planet near the Badlands
to rendezvous with an informer
who claims to have information
on the whereabouts
of the Maquis leader
and former Starfleet officer
Michael Eddington.
Looking for a friend of mine.
His name is Cing'ta.
Cing'ta?
Throw it on the ground.
Turn around.
Hello, Captain.
Eddington.
Mr. Cing'ta
won't be joining us.
His shuttle had an accident
on the way to this rendezvous.
Is he dead?
You just don't understand
the Maquis, do you, Captain?
We're not killers.
Mr. Cing'ta's accident
has marooned him
on a particularly nasty planet
in the Badlands
but I assure you
he's very much alive.
How merciful.
You condemned him
to a slow death.
It's more than he deserved.
He was going
to sell us out to you.
He betrayed us.
Now there's a subject
you know a lot about.
You've been on my tail
for eight months
and now that we're face to face
that's all you have
to say to me?
I will say the rest
at your court-martial.
Tell me, Captain.
What is it
that bothers you more...
the fact that I left Starfleet
to fight for a higher cause
or the fact that it happened
on your watch?
You didn't "leave" Starfleet.
If you had, I wouldn't be here.
You betrayed Starfleet.
You used your position
as Security Chief
to feed the Maquis
information about us
and at the same time,
you misled us
with false information
about them.
There is a word for that...
treason.
Look out there.
Those people... they were
colonists on Salva II.
They had farms and shops
and homes and schools.
And then one day,
the Federation signed a treaty
and handed their world
over to the Cardassians...
just like that.
They made these people
refugees overnight.
It's not that simple
and you know it.
These people don't have
to live here like this.
We've offered them resettlement.
They don't want to be resettled.
They want to go home
to the lives they built.
How would you feel
if the Federation gave
your father's home
to the Cardassians?
I'm not here to debate
Federation policy with...
I didn't tell you
to turn around.
Look at them, Captain.
They're humans,
just like you and me
and Starfleet took
everything away from them.
Remember that the next time
you put on that uniform.
There's a war out there
and you're on the wrong side.
You know what I see out there,
Mr. Eddington?
I see victims
but not of Cardassia
or the Federation.
Victims of you...
the Maquis.
You sold these people
on the dream
that one day they could go back
to those farms and schools
and homes
but you know they never can
and the longer you keep
that hope alive
the longer these people
will suffer.
Go ahead, shoot me.
Someday, I may
take you up on that.
For now, let me leave you
with one piece of advice.
Don't come after me.
You'll regret it.
Sisko to Defiant.
Eddington just beamed out.
Trace his transporter signal.
We've got it, Captain.
He's on a Maquis raider.
They're breaking orbit
and heading out of the system.
Beam me aboard
and lay in a pursuit course.
All hands to battle stations.
Aye, sir.
He's headed for the Badlands,
all right.
Course is zero mark 213.
Commander?
Changing course now
to zero mark 213.
We're on his tail, Captain.
Maximum warp.
How long until we're
in firing range?
22 minutes.
- Major?
- Not good enough.
He'll reach the plasma fields
two minutes
before we're in range.
We need some help.
What's the position
of the Starship Malinche?
They're on patrol in the DMZ,
near the Gamma 7 outpost.
Hmm. Perfect.
Is the new
holocommunicator ready?
Oh, the Chief's had it on line
for six hours now.
I think he's eager for someone
to give it a try.
Always like to please the Chief.
Open a channel to Captain
Sanders on the Malinche.
Are you receiving my image,
Captain?
Yes, and you?
You appear to be sitting
on my Bridge.
It may take me a while
to get used to this.
I'm not fond
of uninvited guests.
I'll try not
to overstay my welcome
but at the moment
I need your help.
We're in pursuit
of a Maquis raider
headed for the Badlands.
Can you intercept?
You seem pretty eager, Captain.
What did this Maquis raider do?
It's not what they did.
It's who's in command...
Michael Eddington.
Ah.
Everyone's favorite traitor.
Captain, if you don't mind...
You want him in your brig.
We'll cut him off.
You can grab him.
Sanders out.
The Malinche is
moving to intercept.
Prepare to target
the Maquis ship.
I want to disable them,
but I want them alive.
Understood.
Send a security detachment
to the transporter room.
Have them prepare to...
Captain, Eddington's
dropped out of warp.
Go to impulse.
Raise shields.
What is he doing?
He's changed course.
Now he's headed directly for us.
He has locked
his weapons on us.
He's no match for the Defiant.
Is this some kind
of suicide run?
Not Eddington.
He's up to something.
Let's not give him a chance
to make his move.
Mr. Worf, fire phasers.
Report.
We've got a massive
computer failure.
Every computer system is down...
and all the backups.
We're losing control over...
everything.
Weapons, navigation,
helm, propulsion...
Bridge to Engine Room.
Commander, get down there.
Find out what's going on.
Try to route the auxiliary
controls through the...
Before you waste a lot of time
running around trying
to restore computer control
let me save you some trouble.
You can't.
You'll find that your memory
cores are completely wiped
and will have to be
reprogrammed from scratch.
These work remarkably well.
Glad we were able
to procure one.
You left a cascade virus
in the Defiant's computers.
Sounds simple, doesn't it?
But I assure you
it took a great deal of time
to devise one
that wouldn't be detected
by Odo or Chief O'Brien.
I'm really quite proud of it.
I'll add it to the list
of charges against you.
Well, as long
as you're making a list
why don't you add this?
You know what your problem is,
Captain?
You've made this personal.
It didn't have to be.
It wasn't with me.
I have no animosity,
no harsh feelings toward you.
I wish I could say the same.
Does it really pay
to risk yourself,
your ship, your crew
on a personal vendetta?
And would Starfleet approve?
I don't need any lectures
about Starfleet from you.
And no matter what happens
here today
it's not over between us.
I'm the one in control here,
Captain.
Your ship is defenseless.
I could destroy you right now
but I won't.
Like I said,
the Maquis aren't killers.
Our quarrel is
with the Cardassians, not you.
Leave us alone
and we'll leave you alone.
Cease fire.
Am I supposed to thank you?
No.
I'm not going to make you
grovel for your life.
Unlike you, Captain,
I know when to walk away.
Maybe you should
think about that...
on your long trip home.
Captain's Log, Stardate 50488.2.
The Defiant has returned
to the station
but not under its own power.
The Starship Malinche
had to tow us home.
We've got our work
cut out for us.
Eddington's cascade
virus disabled
every memory circuit
on the Defiant.
We'll have to reload
and reprogram
the entire database.
How long?
Well, if we were at a shipyard
with a space dock and a crew...
We're not.
How long?
Two weeks.
And that's working
with three shifts
'round the clock.
Get started.
If there's any way
you can speed things up...
I'll do what I can.
I've removed two similar
cascade viruses
hidden on the station's
main computer.
By transmitting a signal
Eddington could have disabled
our entire defense system.
How long until you've eliminated
all of Eddington's handiwork?
It's a good question.
I can't guarantee
we found all of them.
Eddington was DS9's
Chief of Starfleet Security
for 18 months.
He had the opportunity
to infiltrate and compromise
every system on the station.
Then check every system
on the station.
I intend to.
Sir, have you ever reminded
Starfleet Command
that they stationed
Eddington here
because they didn't trust me?
No.
Please do.
What word do you have
from Starfleet Intelligence?
Two Bolian freighters
have disappeared
near the Badlands.
They believe the Maquis
are responsible.
What were
the freighters carrying?
Several thousand tons
of selenium and rhodium nitrite.
That's not very valuable cargo.
What would they want with it?
Commander Dax
is analyzing the possibilities.
Good.
In the meantime,
help Chief O'Brien
get the Defiant back on line.
I want to get out there
as soon as possible.
Aye, sir.
What can I do for you, Captain?
I don't know quite
how to tell you this
so I'll just say it.
Starfleet Command has given me
a new assignment.
They want me
to bring in Eddington.
Oh, you mean
you've been ordered
to help me bring him in,
don't you?
No. Your mission orders
have changed.
Eddington is no longer
your responsibility.
Did they give you a reason?
Well...
you've been after him
for, uh, eight months.
Not to put too fine
a point on it, but...
you haven't gotten the job done.
Look, Captain,
I understand how you feel.
If one of my officers
had fooled me
the way Eddington fooled you,
I...
I'd take it personally, too.
Bad choice of words.
I didn't mean "fooled."
No, you're exactly right.
I was fooled.
But it won't happen again.
That's not the issue.
Starfleet also believes
that where Eddington is
concerned, you're vulnerable.
He just knows you too well,
Captain.
So maybe it's time
for someone he doesn't know
to go after him.
Good hunting.
Thank you, Captain.
The good news is
Starfleet Intelligence
is making progress
breaking the Maquis
communication codes.
The bad news is,
it won't do us any good.
We're out of the game.
But what the hell, right?
You win some, you lose some.
You always had problems
with the "lose some"
part of that.
What can I say, old man?
In 25 years of duty
I have never been
taken off an assignment
until now!
Right.
This is about being
taken off the assignment.
It has nothing to do
with a certain
ex-security officer
we both know.
He worked under me
for a year and a half.
I saw him almost every day
read his reports,
had him to dinner.
I even took him
to a baseball game
in the holosuite once
and I never saw it!
It's my job to be
a good judge of character
and what did I do?
Not only did I not see it,
I put him up for a promotion.
He played his hand well.
He played me, all right.
And what is my excuse?
Is he a changeling?
No.
Is he a being with seven
lifetimes of experience? No.
Is he a wormhole alien?
No.
He's just a man, like me...
and he beat me!
It's good.
"Good"?
It's good you're working it out
on the bag, Benjamin.
Because... you're going
to have to let go of this one.
Eddington is someone
else's problem now
and you're going
to have to live with that.
Ops to Captain Sisko.
What is it, Major?
Sir, you'd better get up here.
There's news
and it's about Eddington.
Report.
Eddington just upped the ante.
He attacked the Cardassian
colony on Veloz Prime
with a biogenic weapon.
What?!
He launched three stratospheric
torpedoes at the planet
and spread cobalt diselenide
throughout the biosphere.
A nerve agent that is
harmless to most humanoids
but it is deadly to Cardassians.
The Cardassians are
already evacuating.
And Eddington has announced
that the Maquis intend
to reclaim the planet
once they are gone.
What I don't understand
is where the Maquis
got the materials
to make a biogenic weapon.
I do.
I should have seen it earlier.
The selenium
and the rhodium nitrites
they hijacked,
can be reformulated
and with some work, synthesized
to produce...
cobalt diselenide.
Where's the Malinche?
On the other side
of the Badlands.
They're headed
for Veloz Prime now
but by the time
they get there...
Eddington will be long gone.
Given the amount
of chemical compounds
Eddington stole
how many of these weapons
will he be able to make?
Enough to poison every
Cardassian colony in the DMZ.
There must something we can do.
Worf, are there any other
starships near Veloz Prime?
The Malinche is our only
ship in the sector.
So unless they stop Eddington...
the Maquis have turned the tide.
There is another ship
in the area.
It's moored at Docking Bay 3.
Defiant.
It's going to be tricky,
Captain.
Only half the systems
are back on line.
And most of those are not
operating at full capacity.
What about the warp drive?
We can go to warp six
but the inertial dampers
haven't been fully repaired
so don't expect a smooth ride.
The weapons are also on line
but the targeting scanners
have to be manually calibrated.
We can shoot, but God knows
what we'll hit.
What about communications?
The Defiant's com system
is fried...
and I do mean fried.
Well, we still have
our com badges.
I'm afraid not.
They won't work either
not with all the interference
from the unshielded
EPS conduits.
Well, what do we use?
Cups and a long string?
We'll have to improvise.
Let me introduce you
to your new com system.
Cadet?
Cadet Nog,
reporting as ordered, sir.
Stand easy.
With most of the Bridge control
functions off line
all orders to Engineering
will have to be relayed.
In the interest of clarity,
I thought it best
that those messages be
relayed with one voice.
Mister Academy here.
I figured you'd want somebody
who could hear you
while the Bridge
is exploding all around you.
Exploding?
We may be going
into a combat situation.
Do you think you're ready
for that, Cadet?
Sir. Yes, sir.
Absolutely, sir.
I'm glad to hear it.
Report to the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
"Exploding"?
Let me give you
all the bad news at once, sir.
We have no cloak,
no transporters
no replicators,
and the stabilizing gyros
are at only 50 percent.
So don't ask for any sharp turns
unless you want to end up
doing barrel rolls.
That could be fun.
Do you have any good news,
Chief?
The new holocommunicator
I installed works perfectly.
Well, let's be thankful
for small favors.
Prepare for departure.
All right, say it.
What?
That I have lost all perspective
that I'm turning this
into a vendetta
between me and Eddington
and that I am putting
the ship, the crew
and my entire career at risk
and if I had any brains at all
I'd go back to my office,
sit down
and read Odo's crime reports.
I wasn't going to say that.
But that's what you
were thinking, right?
No.
Actually,
what I was thinking is...
you're becoming more like Curzon
all the time.
I don't know how to take that.
Consider it a compliment.
And the next time I go off
half-cocked
on some wild-eyed adventure
think back to this moment
and be a little more
understanding.
Recalibrate phaser banks
one and two.
Initialize starboard
and port thrusters.
Captain, Ops has cleared us
for departure.
Very well.
Engine Room,
stand by impulse power.
Engine Room, Bridge.
- Stand by impulse power.
Stand by to increase
deuterium injection rate.
Standing by...
Configure driver coils
for impulse speed.
Processing configuration.
Set EPS taps at level three.
Ops.
Seal the airlock
and release docking clamps.
Close exterior hatches.
Depressurize the airlock.
Detach umbilicals,
clear all moorings.
Thrusters at station keeping.
Initialize deflector field.
Docking clamps released.
Helm, ease us out.
Port and starboard thrusters
at one-quarter.
Bearing 180 mark zero.
Distance from docking ring:
50 meters.
Sixty.
Seventy.
Eighty.
Bring us about, old man.
Hard to port.
Ten degrees pitch.
Minimal power to aft thrusters.
Let the momentum
bring us around.
Hold at five degrees pitch.
We're coming around too fast.
I see it.
Ease off on the port thrusters.
Pitch back to zero degrees.
Pulse starboard thrusters,
point-five-second bursts.
Engine Room,
helm control is sluggish.
Realign the navigational gyros.
...Realign navigational gyros.
Port thruster,
two second burst.
Double pulse port thruster.
Helm, I hope you see that pylon.
Bow thrusters,
pitch up 16 degrees.
Full power to port thrusters.
Half roll... now.
Engine Room.
One-quarter impulse power.
Engine Room, Bridge.
Helm, lay in a course
for the Badlands.
Engine Room,
stand by for warp speed.
Set intermix to point zero-one.
Initialize warp
chamber on my mark.
Three, two, one.
Mark.
Warp one, sir.
Engine Room,
increase speed to warp six
as soon as possible.
...to warp six
Sir, Engine Room reports
we could go to warp seven.
Well done, people.
Mr. Worf, I think
we should start running
battle drills.
Aye, sir.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
After completing a series
of readiness drills
we've entered the plasma fields
of the Badlands
and begun our search
for Eddington.
Steady as she goes.
Watch those gyros.
Check the status of torpedoes
three and four.
We have an energy variance
on the plasma warheads.
Transfer power from the...
Forward scanners are
still not functioning.
Engine Room, where are
those field stabilizers?
Engine Room, Bridge.
Where are those
field stabilizers?
Major, Engine Room
reports field stabilizers
should be on line
in 15 minutes.
Oh, I've got something.
It's a small neutrino signature,
bearing...
218 mark 135.
Distance...
approximately 900 kilometers.
It's moving.
It's a Maquis raider.
Helm, set intercept course.
Engine Room,
three-quarter impulse.
Incoming transmission
from the Maquis raider.
It's Eddington.
Put him through.
Well, well, Mr. Eddington.
You just couldn't resist
the temptation
to come after me,
could you, Captain?
I like to finish what I start.
Well, I'm afraid you're going
to be disappointed...
again.
You won't get me, Captain.
But I do have
a consolation prize for you.
Actually, it's more of a gift.
Incoming transmission.
Sending over a document.
It's a book.
One of my favorites.
Les Misérables.
Thank you, but I've read it.
Recently?
If not, you should
read it again.
Pay close attention
to the character
of Inspector Javert...
the French policeman who spends
20 years chasing a man
for stealing a loaf of bread.
Sound like anyone you know?
Why don't you beam over
and we'll discuss it?
Captain, closing
on the Maquis ship.
700 kilometers.
Ready weapons.
Phaser banks charged.
Lock target.
Locked.
It's over, Eddington.
Why don't you surrender
your vessel
and prepare to be boarded?
It's a tempting offer,
but I have other plans.
Enjoy the book.
Sir, the neutrino readings
are dissipating.
It's not a ship.
It's an unmanned probe
set to transmit
a false warp signature.
He wanted to lure us here.
Why?
He's up to something...
outside the plasma fields.
Helm, bring us about.
Get us out of here.
Engines at full impulse.
Engine Room, Bridge...
Hard to port.
Full thrusters.
Course 180 mark zero.
Sir, Chief O'Brien
doesn't recommend
increasing velocity
through the plasma fields.
Objection noted.
Now get me more speed.
Engine Room, Bridge.
More speed.
Sir, picking up
a distress signal.
It's the Starship Malinche.
They've been ambushed
by the Maquis.
It's dead in space.
How can we help you, Captain?
Our warp core matrix
compositor is fused.
Our navigational systems
are disabled.
If you could spare
some micro-power relays
we should have the engines
back on line in a day or two.
Engine Room.
Beam a damage control team
to the Malinche.
Tell them to take along
a dozen micro-power relays.
Engine Room...
We got a distress signal
from a Cardassian freighter.
They'd just been attacked
by the Maquis.
Suffered some casualties.
Our sensors confirmed
what we were being told
but when we lowered the shields
to transport
some of the wounded...
The sensor readings
had been faked.
There were no Cardassians
on that freighter.
The Maquis had rigged it
with a focused particle beam
that punched
through our gyro shielding
and we lost helm control.
And by the time we got
back on our feet again
three Maquis raiders
came out of the plasma field.
Well...
it seems I couldn't get the job
done either, Captain.
It's not over.
I figured you'd
be going after him.
We have something
that might be useful to you.
We intercepted a coded message
from one of Eddington's raiders.
Maybe you can decode it.
Our, uh, computers
are still down.
I appreciate it.
Do me a favor?
Of course.
Save me a seat
at his court-martial.
Count on it.
Good hunting, Captain.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
With the Defiant's computers
still not fully operational
we're relying on Odo,
back at Deep Space 9
to decipher the Maquis message.
In the meantime,
we're combing the DMZ
in the hopes of a chance
encounter with Eddington
but with each passing hour,
our hopes are fading.
Sir, incoming transmission.
It's Odo.
Captain.
Odo, we need
some good news around here.
Tell me that you have some.
Possibly.
I've analyzed
the Maquis message.
And?
It appears to be a simple
Breen nursery rhyme.
A heterophonic,
five-line verse.
Quite a catchy one, too.
What does it mean?
Well, metrical analysis
shows an alternating tetrameter
and pentameter structure
but the computer could find no
meaningful pattern in the words.
They appear to be
just what they are...
nonsensical phrases strung
together because they rhyme...
at least to the Breen.
And the music?
It's written on a Lyxian scale.
I ran it
through the computer, too.
No meaningful pattern.
So we're nowhere.
Now, I wouldn't say that.
You see, I remembered something
that Eddington once said to me.
"The best place to hide
something is in plain sight."
And since this is
a Breen nursery rhyme...
So you think that Eddington
is using the music as a signal
for a rendezvous
in the Breen system?
Or a Breen settlement
like the one on Portas V,
which isn't far from the DMZ.
The biogenic components of the
weapons Eddington's been using
are very bulky
and very unstable.
They need to be kept
in a large, sophisticated
cold-storage unit.
And if anyone knows how to keep
things cold, it's the Breen.
Thank you, Odo.
Captain.
Mr. Worf, do we have a series
of sensor relays near Portas V?
Yes, sir.
Two class-5 intelligence drones.
Pull their sensor logs.
I want to see who's been
visiting the Breen system.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Odo's hunch has proven accurate.
Our intelligence drones
detected a Maquis freighter
entering Portas V
three hours ago.
The freighter was last seen
headed into the Dorvan sector
of the DMZ.
Considering the freighter's
range, velocity and heading
Eddington's next target is one
of four Cardassian colonies.
But...
these targets are unlikely.
Their defense systems
were recently upgraded
by the Cardassians.
Hmm.
Eddington isn't looking
for a fight.
That leaves only Quatal
and Panora.
Quatal has a lucrative
mining operation,
and their weapon systems
are in the process
of being upgraded
but they're not
fully operational.
A tempting target.
Not as tempting as Panora.
The Maquis attacked
them two months ago.
And most of their defense
systems were severely damaged.
They're almost helpless.
And there are constant
ion storms in that system...
good places to hide
if you want to mount
a surprise attack.
A tactic Eddington knows well.
Panora is a more logical
target than Quatal.
Then Eddington will attack
Quatal.
Sir?
He likes being unpredictable.
Approaching Quatal Prime.
Slow to impulse power.
Full scan.
Activate parabolic
sensor arrays.
Initiate lateral scanners.
We're too late, Captain.
Eddington's detonated
his weapon.
The nerve agent
is already spreading
through the planet's atmosphere.
Which means the
Cardassians don't have
much time to get away.
Eddington's always
one step ahead of us.
Maybe not this time.
I'm reading residual
neutrino levels.
Looks like one,
maybe two Maquis raiders
behind the fourth moon.
They're on the run.
Go after them.
Full impulse.
Engine Room, Bridge.
On screen.
Shields up.
Charge phaser banks.
Aye, sir.
How long to intercept?
15 seconds.
Prepare to lock targets.
Targeting sequence on...
Hard to port.
Stick with this one, old man.
They've locked phasers on us.
Power to forward shields.
Forward shields, on line.
Restabilize port and...
Lock target.
Targeting scanners...
synchronized.
Fire!
Helm, bring us about.
One more to go.
Sir, this one's making
another run for the planet.
I don't get it... they've
already poisoned the atmosphere.
More speed.
Engine Room, Bridge.
They've locked phasers
on one of the transport ships
evacuating the Cardassians.
They've disabled the transport.
It's losing power.
It's going down.
Can we beam the crew off?
We're out of transporter range.
Incoming transmission.
Well, Javert...
let's see how deep
your obsession with me is.
You've got me.
I can't outrun or outfight
the Defiant, but...
if you come after me,
you'll have to pay a price...
you'll have to let
all those helpless Cardassians
spiral down to their deaths.
The choice is yours.
How long do they have?
Two minutes to impact.
Not much time.
Probably take you
at least a minute
to get back to the planet.
They're just Cardassians.
Helm, bring us about.
Prepare to engage tractor beam.
Initializing tractor beam.
Aligning induction field.
Alignment complete.
We've towed the transport ship
out of the planet's
gravitational pull.
Once our repair team
is back on board
release the tractor beam.
The Cardassians can
limp their way home
in a day or two.
Les Misérables?
You know it?
I can't stand Victor Hugo.
I tried reading
The Hunchback of Notre Dame
but I couldn't get through it.
It was so melodramatic
and his heroines are
so two-dimensional.
Eddington compares me
to one of the characters...
Inspector Javert...
a policeman who
relentlessly pursues
a man named Valjean.
Guilty of a trivial offense.
And in the end
Javert's own inflexibility
destroys him.
He commits suicide.
You can't believe
that description fits you.
Eddington is just trying
to... get under your skin.
He did that eight months ago.
What strikes me about this book
is that Eddington said that
it's one of his favorites.
There's no accounting for taste.
Oh, let's think about it.
A Starfleet security officer
is fascinated
by a nineteenth-century
French melodrama, and now
he's a leader of the Maquis...
a resistance group
fighting the noble battle
against the "evil" Cardassians.
It sounds like he's living out
his own fantasy.
Mm-hmm.
Exactly.
And you know what?
Les Misérables isn't
about the policeman.
It's about Valjean... the victim
of a monstrous injustice
who spends his entire
life helping people.
Making noble sacrifices
for others.
That's how Eddington
sees himself.
He's Valjean.
He's Robin Hood.
He's a romantic, dashing figure
fighting the good fight
against insurmountable odds.
The secret life
of Michael Eddington.
How does it help us?
Well, Eddington is the hero
of his own story.
That makes me the villain.
And what is it
that every hero wants to do?
Kill the bad guy.
Ah, that's part of it.
Heroes only kill
when they have to.
Eddington could have killed me
back at the refugee camp
or when he disabled the Defiant
but, in the best melodramas,
the villain creates a situation
where the hero is forced
to sacrifice himself
for the people, for the cause...
one final, grand gesture.
What are you getting at,
Benjamin?
I think it's time
for me to become the villain.
Commander.
Prepare two quantum torpedoes.
Have Engineering
attach a cargo pod
with 200 kilograms of trilithium
to each torpedo.
Yes, sir, but...
But what?
The extra mass of a cargo pod
will make the torpedo
less effective.
Maquis raiders are small
and maneuverable.
I'm not planning to fire
at any ships, Mr. Worf.
Major.
What is the nearest
Maquis colony?
Solosos III.
Less than an hour away.
Helm, set a course
for Solosos III.
Aye, sir.
Major, I want you to send
the following message
on all Maquis frequencies.
"To all the members
of the Maquis resistance.
"This is Captain Sisko
of the USS Defiant.
"In response to the Maquis' use
of biogenic weapons
"in their recent attacks
"I am about to take
the following action.
"In exactly one hour
I will detonate
two quantum torpedoes
"that will scatter trilithium
resin into the atmosphere
"of Solosos III.
"I thereby will make
the planet uninhabitable
"to all human life
for the next 50 years.
I suggest evacuation plans
begin immediately."
What are you
waiting for, people?
Carry out your orders.
Set torpedo targets
to 50 kilometers
above ground level.
Aye, sir.
Lock.
Ready, Captain.
Time?
One minute left.
And still no transport ship
activity
or any other sign
they're beginning to evacuate.
Commander Worf, prepare
to fire torpedoes on my mark.
Detach safeties
on torpedoes one and two.
Incoming transmission.
It's Eddington.
What are you really
up to, Javert?
Do you expect me to believe
that a decorated
Starfleet officer...
the pride of the service...
is going to poison
an entire planet?
That's exactly
what I'm going to do.
You're bluffing.
Am I?
Commander, launch torpedoes.
Commander, I said
launch torpedoes.
Aye, sir.
The trilithium resin
is dissipating
throughout the biosphere.
The Maquis are scrambling
their transport ships.
They're starting
to evacuate.
Do you realize what you've done?
I've only just begun.
I'm going to eliminate
every Maquis colony
in the DMZ.
You're talking about turning
hundreds of thousands of people
into homeless refugees.
That's right.
When you attacked the Malinche,
you proved one thing...
that the Maquis have become
an intolerable threat
to the security
of the Federation
and I am going
to eliminate that threat.
But think about those people
you saw in the caves
huddled and starving.
They didn't attack the Malinche.
You should have thought
about that
before you attacked
a Federation starship.
Helm, lay in a course
for Tracken II, warp six.
Commander, prepare
two more torpedoes.
Engine Room, Bridge.
Set course 050 mark 179.
Unlock safeties
on torpedoes three and four.
Can't you see
what's happening to you?
You're going against everything
you claim to believe in.
And for what?
To satisfy a personal vendetta?
You betrayed your uniform!
And you're betraying yours,
right now.
The sad part is,
you don't even realize it.
I feel sorry for you, Captain.
This obsession with me...
look what it's cost you.
Major!
Shut that thing off.
Commander Worf,
prepare to launch torpedoes.
Wait!
Lf...
you call off your attack
I'll turn over
all our biogenic weapons.
Not enough.
All right, Javert.
I'll give you what you want...
me.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Resettlement efforts
in the DMZ are underway.
The Cardassian
and Maquis colonists
who were forced
to abandon their homes
will make new lives
for themselves
on the planets
their counterparts evacuated.
The balance in the region
will be restored
though the situation
remains far from stable.
Captain. Commander.
Welcome home.
It's good to be back.
I gather your trip
was productive.
Constable.
This way.
Benjamin, I'm curious.
Your plan to poison
the Maquis planets...
you didn't clear it
with Starfleet first, did you?
I knew I'd forgotten
to do something.
Ah. Big gamble.
That's what it takes
to be a good villain.
You know, sometimes I like it
when the bad guy wins.