Where do you want me
to put this?
Anywhere you can find room.
I bet you can't wait
to put all this together
so you can start shape-shifting
around the room again.
Oh, I suppose.
Though I did enjoy
sleeping in a bed.
Well, there's nothing
to stop you from sleeping
in a bed if you want to.
Except that now when I'm asleep
I tend to revert
to my gelatinous state
and slide onto the floor.
No, the bed goes.
I'm a changeling, not a solid.
There's no use
pretending otherwise.
I guess we can put
all this in storage.
What about these padds?
Uh...
Finding and Winning
Your Perfect Mate
by Doctor Jennings Rain.
I'll take that.
I thought I was going
to be a humanoid
for the rest of my life.
There were certain things...
You don't have to explain, Odo.
I only read
the first three chapters.
Maybe you should finish it.
Why waste my time?
Romance is for solids.
Well, you are a solid,
18 hours a day.
I'm sure there are plenty
of women on this station
who would be
very interested in you
if you gave them a chance.
I'll keep that in mind, Major.
Right now, I'd be satisfied
just getting this room in order.
Dax to Kira and Odo.
Go ahead, Commander.
There's something we'd like you
to take a look at in Ops.
We're on our way.
One of our listening posts
in the Gamma Quadrant
picked this up
a few minutes ago.
It looks like
a Cardassian military code
but the computer
doesn't recognize it.
Oh, it's Cardassian, all right.
But I didn't think
there were any Cardassians
in the Gamma Quadrant.
None that we know of.
Not Elgol-red
or Fifth Order
Military Encryption.
Try Courier Code Five-Nine.
Strange.
Most Cardassian codes
use a recursive
encryption algorithm
but this has a completely
different coding system.
Bajoran Intelligence
has a lot of experience
breaking Cardassian codes.
Why don't you send it to them?
We did, as soon as it came in.
We still haven't
heard from them.
It may take some time.
If someone's sending
coded Cardassian messages
from the Gamma Quadrant
I want to know
what they're saying, now.
We do have an expert
in Cardassian codes
living on the station.
You're right.
Dax, get me Mr. Garak.
It's good to see you
again, Cara.
I'm sorry for the interruption.
Well, how did it go?
I'm afraid I disappointed them.
I think they were hoping
that the message they picked up
would contain the key
to defeating the Dominion.
You should have seen
the looks on their faces
when I explained
to them that it was
a five-year-old
planetary survey report.
A planetary survey report?
That's the look, exactly.
I would have thought you'd be
a little disappointed, too.
After all, it could have been
from one of the survivors
of the Cardassian fleet that
was lost in the Gamma Quadrant.
Oh, I'd given up hope
of ever finding any trace
of them long ago.
Really?
I never saw you
as the giving-up type.
There comes a time when one
must face reality, my dear.
Those people are gone
and are never coming back.
Well... my young friends
I'd like to stay here
and chat all day
but I have dresses to make,
trousers to mend.
It's a full life,
if a trifle banal.
And do tell Captain Sisko
that I'd be more than happy
to decode any Cardassian laundry
lists that come across his desk.
My dear.
My father would be furious
to hear me say this
but... there's something
about Garak I find...
fascinating.
Yes, he has his moments.
Going somewhere?
I really must remember to stop
underestimating you, Doctor.
How did you know?
You mean, that you were lying
about the contents
of the message?
You said you'd given up
on the Cardassian survivors
who were lost
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Well, Ziyal was right.
You're not the giving-up sort.
Very good, Doctor.
You've come a long way
from the naive young man
I met five years ago.
You've become distrustful
and suspicious.
It suits you.
I had a good teacher.
What did the message
really say, Garak?
It was a call for help...
from Enabran Tain.
Tain?
But you said you'd seen his ship
destroyed by the Dominion.
I did, but Tain was head of
the Obsidian Order for 20 years.
If he can survive that,
he can survive anything.
I have to find him, Doctor.
I owe it to him.
You don't owe Tain anything.
He had you exiled
from Cardassia.
Yes, but, aside from that,
we were very close.
He was... my mentor
and I'm not going
to turn my back on him.
If it'll make you feel any
better, you can come with me.
All you have to do
is come up with an excuse
why you need the runabout,
and we could leave immediately.
So, let me get this straight.
You want me to lie
to my commanding officer
violate Starfleet regulations
and go with you on a mission
into the Gamma Quadrant
which will probably
get us both killed.
I'm ready when you are.
In that case...
let's go.
To Captain Sisko's office.
How do you know
that the message isn't a fake?
That it was really sent by Tain?
The code sequence was
personally designed
by Tain and myself.
No one else knows it.
Now, somehow he got
that message out
and I have to follow it
back to its source.
Did the message contain
any coordinates?
No. Most of it
was identification code.
The rest of it
was just one word, "alive,"
repeated over and over again.
So it should be easy enough
to triangulate the source.
Captain...
Tain might not be alone.
There could be others.
Troops from the
Cardassian-Romulan fleet
survivors from the Dominion
attack on New Bajor
and even crew members
from those Federation ships
that disappeared
in the Gamma Quadrant.
This is a mission of mercy.
You can't ignore it.
I'm still not totally convinced
that it's a genuine message.
But I suppose there's
only one way to find out.
Captain, you can't let him go.
It's too dangerous.
Your concern is touching, Doctor
but I assure you,
I can take care of myself.
Maybe you can, but you're
still not going alone.
Doctor?
I think you've just volunteered.
Dr. Bashir isn't going anywhere.
But I do have
someone else in mind.
I don't know
what makes me angrier...
that you agreed to go
into the Gamma Quadrant
with Garak
or that I had to hear it
from Sisko.
I was going to tell you.
When?
On your way out the airlock?
A Klingon warrior
does not have to explain
why he chooses to face danger,
not even to his par'machkai.
So in other words, you were
afraid I'd make a scene.
That I'd embarrass you,
maybe even cry.
You are capable of anything.
Don't worry, Worf.
I won't be shedding any tears
over you.
Ah. Then you came to wish me
a good death in battle.
No.
I came for these.
My Klingon operas.
Well, you won't be using them
for the next few days.
Somebody might as well
enjoy them.
What?
Something wrong?
You have a tendency
to misplace things.
And you're afraid
that I might... lose
your precious operas?
Yes.
It's a distinct possibility.
If I were you, I'd hurry back.
That is, if you want to keep
your collection intact.
Have a glorious death...
or don't.
It's up to you.
The Gamma Quadrant?
You can't go
to the Gamma Quadrant.
Oh, I can... and I will.
I have to.
But if something were
to happen to you, I...
I don't know what I'd do.
Oh, I'm sure you could find
someone else
to eat your meals with.
Not that you'd have to.
I fully intend to return.
It's not just the meals.
Yes, I know.
I'm the only other Cardassian
on the station.
It's not that, either.
You know that.
It's just that...
you're intelligent
and cultured...
and kind.
My dear, you're young
so I realize that you're
a poor judge of character.
Why do you always make fun
of my feelings for you?
Perhaps because I find them
a bit, uh, misguided?
Well, if this is what you think
why do you spend
so much time with me?
Because I'm exiled... and alone,
and a long way from home.
And when I'm with you
it doesn't feel so bad.
I'm glad I could help.
Ziyal...
no matter what happens
no matter how bleak
things may look
I promise you I will come back.
You have my word.
I believe you.
Take your hands off her!
Father, no!
You touch my daughter again
I'll kill you.
Father...
let him go.
Please!
Go ahead. Kill me.
She'll never forgive you,
you know.
Gentlemen!
Gentlemen.
I don't know
what's going on here
but I'm sure it's no excuse
to act like a pair of Klingons.
I'll act as I please, Ferengi.
Then you'll excuse me
while I call Security.
I'm sure Odo
will get a big thrill
out of having you locked up
in one of his holding cells.
Father... please.
Public opinion seems to be
running against you.
You know... I think that
actually helped my back.
Let's go, Garak.
I'll buy you a drink.
A pleasure...
as always, my dear.
You do have a lovely daughter.
She must take
after her mother.
You're wrong about Garak,
Father.
He's a good man.
You have no idea
how much it pains me
to hear you say that.
It is good to see you again,
Ziyal.
It's good to see you,
too, Father.
What are you doing
on the station?
Oh, I had a little skirmish
with a Klingon battle cruiser.
My ship was damaged,
so I came here for repairs
and to spend
some time with you.
And I can see...
we have a lot to talk about.
Remember, this is
a reconnaissance mission.
You are to avoid Dominion
ships at all costs.
I want you back
here in one piece.
What about Garak?
I want him back, too.
I suppose
I don't have to tell you
to keep a close eye on him.
At the first sign of betrayal,
I will kill him
but I promise
to return the body intact.
I assume that's a joke.
We will see.
You want me
to sponsor your application
to Starfleet Academy?
What do you think?
I think it is a bad idea.
Well, I'd write the
actual letter myself.
I just need you to sign it.
Find someone else.
Why?
Because I'm a Cardassian?
You're a Klingon.
Nog is a Ferengi.
Starfleet Academy is
a very accepting place.
You are not just a Cardassian.
You are a spy, an assassin
and a saboteur.
I know I've done
some unfortunate things
in the past, and I regret them.
That's why I want
to join Starfleet
why I need to join Starfleet.
I'm looking for a fresh start
a way to make up for all
the damage I've done.
I need to prove to myself
that I can be better than I am
but I need your help
your support
to start me on my way...
to redemption.
If that is how you feel,
I will...
consider your request.
That's all I ask.
Frankly, I think I can be
quite an asset to Starfleet.
With my extensive experience,
I could skip the lower ranks
entirely and begin my career
as a Commander.
Maybe you should suggest that
in your letter.
Tell them you'd be honored
to serve under me.
Do not play games with me.
You have no desire
to join Starfleet, do you?
No, I'm afraid I don't.
Then why all of this deception?
Because lying is a skill
like any other
and if you want to maintain
a level of excellence, you have
to practice constantly.
Practice on someone else.
Mr. Worf
you're no fun at all.
Good.
Major...
you and I have to talk.
Ah, Dukat, I've had a busy day.
I just want to drink my coffee...
I left my daughter in your care.
You promised me
you would look after her.
I trusted you.
Listen, if this is about
taking Ziyal to services
at the Bajoran shrine...
I'm not talking
about exposing her
to your backwards superstitions.
She's half Bajoran.
That's part
of her cultural heritage.
I understand that.
I'm talking about Garak.
What about him?
She's in love with him!
Oh...
I wouldn't call it love.
So you've known about this
all along
and you've done nothing
to stop it?
She was lonely.
The last time I checked
he's the only other Cardassian
living on the station.
The man is a heartless,
cold-blooded killer.
Like I said, he's a Cardassian.
Your daughter is a grown woman
capable of making
her own decisions.
I'm not fond of Garak, and I...
may even think that
their friendship is a mistake
but, the way I see it,
that's her prerogative.
You did this on purpose,
didn't you?
Did what?
Allowed my daughter
to associate with a man
you knew was my enemy.
Stood by while
he whispered poison in her ear
and all under the guise
of doing me a favor.
No, Dukat, let's get
one thing straight.
I didn't bring Ziyal
to the station for you.
I did it for her
because I knew it would be
better for her to be here
than being a soldier
fighting in your private
little war with the Klingons.
Save your excuses, Major.
You've betrayed me
and I promise I won't forget it.
If that's a threat...
I'm not impressed.
There was a time when Bajorans
took Cardassian threats
very seriously.
Not anymore.
Good day, Major.
Good day.
I just don't see why
these runabout replicators
can't provide
a more varied menu.
I'd like to get my hands
on that fellow Earl Grey
and tell him a thing or two
about tea leaves.
We've just dropped out of warp.
Is there something wrong?
We can go no further.
What do you mean?
My readings indicate
the source of that coded signal
is deep in Dominion space.
I have strict orders
to avoid unnecessary risk.
We must turn back.
Well, I certainly
don't want to take
an unnecessary risk,
but our sensors show no sign
of Jem'Hadar warships
in this area.
True, but the likelihood
of contact will increase
from this point on,
and my orders were very clear.
But we've come all this way.
To turn around now
without an answer...
it seems so... un-Klingon.
I am also a Starfleet officer.
Why don't we go
through this nebula?
We can avoid detection,
and get light years closer
to the source
of the transmission.
Our shields would be
useless in that nebula.
But so would Jem'Hadar sensors.
The answer is out there,
Commander.
We just have to have
the courage to find it.
And remember, it's not
just Tain we're looking for.
The Maryland, the Proxima,
the Sarajevo...
Starfleet ships
that have been lost
in the Gamma Quadrant for years
and their crews... brave soldiers
warriors of the Federation,
unaccounted for.
We owe it to them
to do everything in our power
to find them
and bring them home.
It's the honorable thing to do.
You use that word, but you have
no idea what it means.
Maybe not... but you do.
Setting course for the nebula.
There's a pocket
of toh-maire gas ahead of us.
Bringing her to 031 mark 355.
Steady as she...
Now what could that be?
Whatever they are
they are coming right at us.
Maybe this wasn't
such a good idea after all.
You still haven't lost them.
I know that.
There are
four more Jem'Hadar ships
in close pursuit
and at least two ahead of us
on an intercept course.
We must warn the station.
There is only one reason
for the Dominion
to hide such a large fleet
this close to the wormhole.
You think they're planning
to attack the Alpha Quadrant?
I'm certain of it.
Your message is transmitting
but it's hard to tell
if it's getting through
all this interference.
We've got to get clear
of the nebula.
What happened?
We've just come to a dead stop.
They have us in a tractor beam.
Repolarize the hull.
Try to shake us loose.
Ah... are we glad to see you.
Could one of you point us
in the direction
of the wormhole?
I'm telling you,
he knows exactly who I am.
Kirayoshi already recognizes me.
Nerys, the O'Brien's baby
is less than a month old.
He doesn't recognize
his own fingers.
He spent seven months
inside my belly
listening to my heartbeat
hearing my voice.
There's a connection there.
Every time I walk
into the room, he smiles.
It's probably gas.
Thanks.
You always know just
the right thing to say.
How's my baby boy?
He recognized me.
Did he?
Hold on... I'm getting
a priority one distress signal
from the Gamma Quadrant.
Dax to Sisko.
You better come out here.
What is it?
I've got a message from Worf,
but it's badly garbled.
Maybe I can clean it up.
It says "Jem'Hadar"
and then some coordinates
I can't make out.
"Build up" and then...
Go on.
It ends with "imminent."
"Imminent"?
We just lost contact
with two of our listening posts
in the Gamma Quadrant.
The Dominion... they're coming.
Notify Starfleet Command.
Put the station on Yellow Alert.
Make sure everyone knows
this is not a drill.
Major, I want you
to take the Defiant
into the Gamma Quadrant.
Locate Mr. Worf.
Find out what the hell's
going on there.
And if an invasion fleet
is on the way?
Then get back here
as soon as possible
and God help us all.
Ah, good.
You look like the man in charge.
I was just trying to explain
to your colleagues here
that this is all
an unfortunate misunderstanding.
Cardassians are all alike.
You talk too much.
Let him go.
I give the orders here.
Release me... or die.
Worf...
do as he says.
This is Internment Camp 371.
You are here because you
are enemies of the Dominion.
There is no release, no escape
except death.
Another listening post
has gone dead
and the one closest
to the wormhole
is detecting an incoming ship.
Picking up an increase
in neutrino levels.
Something's coming through.
Shields fully charged.
Weapons ready.
The wormhole's opening.
On screen.
It's the Defiant.
We're being hailed.
Put it through.
Major, what have you found?
Trouble.
Father?
Ah.
Have you been waiting long?
Not long.
You should've come
into the shrine.
No, I don't think so.
So, where would you
like to have dinner?
Forget about dinner.
I want you to go back
to your quarters
and pack your things.
There's a ship leaving
for Cardassia in the morning.
I want you on it.
You're sending me to Cardassia?
I've just learned
there's a Dominion fleet
headed for the wormhole.
This place is not safe
any longer.
Father, I'm not sure
that I want to go.
Ziyal.
There's nothing to discuss.
I'm not going to let
any harm come to you.
Now, I think you'd better
get ready to leave.
Hmm?
They have been scanned.
They have no weapons
and their identities
have been confirmed.
Very well.
You will be sheltered
in Barracks 6.
You are free to move about
the compound
but remember,
beyond the atmospheric dome
there is nothing
but airless vacuum
and barren rock.
Leave the dome,
even for an instant
and you die.
We'll keep that in mind.
I've been waiting for another...
Klingon.
General Martok.
Enough!
It's over.
But for you,
it's just beginning.
Do I know you?
I am Worf, son of Mogh.
Yes, I've heard of you.
How long have you been here?
Two years.
Aren't you Klingons
supposed to kill yourselves
when you're taken prisoner?
Not when there are
still enemies to fight.
Or hope of escape.
If you... are Worf...
then you must be Garak.
He said you would come.
There.
Tain.
What is wrong with him?
It's his heart.
Really?
There are many people who'd say
he doesn't have one.
He was convinced
that you would come.
He knew I had no choice.
Tain.
Tain, I'm here.
My message...
it got through?
It did.
Where are the others?
There are no others.
Just Commander Worf
and me.
You allowed yourselves
to be taken prisoner?
I taught you better than that.
Living on that station
has dulled your wits.
That's it?
After I've come all this way
after all I've been through
that's all you have
to say to me?
What do you want me to say?
I want you to say
"Thank you, Elim.
"Your loyalty
is most gratifying.
I knew I could count on you."
But I couldn't count on you,
could I?
All you've done
is to doom us...
both.
Sorry I'm late.
What's he doing here?
Captain Sisko invited me.
A Dominion invasion
of the Alpha Quadrant
will affect Cardassia
every bit as much
as it's going to affect us.
Besides, we need all the help
we can get.
The Dominion picked
a perfect time to invade.
The Cardassian fleet
is in shambles.
The Romulans are
not much better off.
And between the Klingon war
and the recent Borg attack
Starfleet's spread pretty thin.
Then we're going to have
our hands full.
There are at least 50
Dominion ships headed our way.
For all we know, that could
just be the first wave.
How soon can we expect
reinforcements to get here?
At maximum warp, two days.
Not soon enough.
What help can we expect
from Cardassia?
My ship and my crew
are at your disposal.
One ship.
Things are looking brighter.
Right now, there's no way
we can beat the Dominion.
Our only hope is
to prevent their fleet
from entering
the Alpha Quadrant.
You're going to destroy
the wormhole?
It's always been a final option.
I'd hoped to never use it.
But the Celestial Temple,
the Prophets...
Professor Kahn
of the Trill Science Ministry
has come up with a way
to seal the wormhole
without damaging it
or harming the Prophets.
But Bajor will be cut off
from the Celestial Temple.
Well, history has shown
whenever the Prophets want
to communicate with Bajor
they find a way.
- But...
- It's either that
or Bajor becomes
the first Dominion target.
We'll have to remodulate
the deflector grid frequencies
and rig a phase-conjugate
graviton beam.
You and Dax start working
immediately.
What about Worf?
If we close
the wormhole, he and Garak
will be trapped
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Casualties... of war.
They have 36 hours
to find their way home.
Let's hope they can make it.
Dismissed.
Before this asteroid
was converted into a prison
the Dominion used
to mine ultritium here.
There was no dome.
Each one of these barracks
had its own life-support system
embedded in the walls.
And Tain was able to modify
that life-support system
and create
a subspace transmitter.
Yes.
There's a crawl space
just behind those panels.
He spent hours in there
working every day
for months on end.
Cardassians...
they're clever people.
Especially that one.
But in just a few days, at best
he'll be dead.
Then it is up to us
to be clever.
They're releasing
him from isolation.
Good.
Who?
A friend.
Move!
B-negative, in case
you were wondering.
Well, it appears we are all
who we seem to be.
If the blood screenings
can be trusted.
It's all we've got.
What about the others?
Have they been tested?
Everyone except that Breen.
No blood.
When were you brought here?
Over a month ago.
I was attending a burn-treatment
conference on Meezan IV.
I went to bed one night
and woke up here.
The same thing happened to me
except I was hunting sabre bear
out on Kang's Summit.
Little did I know,
I was being stalked as well.
And now I'm told the changeling
that replaced me
has caused the death
of countless Klingons.
It is a grave dishonor.
You are not to blame.
I can only imagine
what my replacement
is up to on the station.
We must escape and warn
Captain Sisko
before that changeling
carries out his mission.
Creating a precisely
modulated graviton field
to seal the wormhole
won't be as easy
as Lenara thought.
She was always a lot stronger
on theory than execution.
But we'll get it.
I'm sure you will.
Julian!
What are you doing
up this early?
You've been working
for 16 hours straight.
I thought you could do
with some sandwiches.
That's very thoughtful.
You're a gentlemen
and a scholar.
Truer words were never spoken.
Oh, if you need anything,
anything at all, let me know.
Ah! It's about time.
You almost missed
your transport.
Where's your baggage?
Never mind.
I'll have it sent to you.
That won't be necessary, Father.
I'm not leaving.
Ziyal...
I know we haven't spent
much time together
but I think you know me
well enough to realize
that when I give an order,
I expect to be obeyed.
I'm not one of your soldiers.
No... you're my daughter.
I'm Tora Naprem's daughter, too.
I am half Bajoran.
I don't belong on Cardassia.
You know
I will never be accepted there.
Ziyal, you have to trust me.
Things are going to change
on Cardassia.
- What things?
- I don't have
time to explain.
You're leaving now.
I can't go.
It's him, isn't it?!
That despicable tailor.
You don't want to leave
because you're waiting for him?
Garak promised me
that he would come back.
Listen to me, Ziyal.
He's never coming back.
He's probably dead already
and even if he isn't
the Federation is going
to seal the wormhole.
Garak will be trapped
on the other side.
He made a promise...
and so did I.
I said I would wait for him
and I will.
Is a promise...
to an enemy of your family
more important
than obeying your father?
So be it.
Stay here if that's
what you want.
Stay here and be damned.
I should never have come here.
I should have let
that monster die
forgotten and alone.
Frankly, I'm glad you came.
Misery loves company.
All my life I've done nothing
but try to please that man.
I let him mold me...
let him turn me into
a mirror image of himself.
And how did he repay me?
With exile.
But I forgave him.
And here, in the end,
I thought maybe
just maybe,
he could forgive me.
From what I've seen of him
over the past month
he doesn't come across
as the forgiving type.
I've been a fool.
Let this be a lesson
to you, Doctor.
Perhaps the most valuable
one I can ever teach you.
Sentiment is the greatest
weakness of all.
If that's true
it's a lesson
I'd rather not learn.
I thought
you might want to know...
if you wish to speak
to Tain... do it now
before it's too late.
Elim...
Elim, is that you?
It's me.
Everything's gone dark.
I can't see you.
Are you alone?
Yes.
There's no one else
but you and me.
Surjak, Memad, Brun...
they can't be trusted.
They must be dealt with.
I've already taken care of it.
And what about Gul Vorlem?
Were you able to contact him?
Years ago.
The Romulan ambassador?
He's gone.
All your enemies are dead.
Good.
A man shouldn't allow
his enemies to outlive him.
Then you can die happy.
Unless you still consider me
your enemy.
Elim...
promise me one thing.
I'm listening.
Don't die here.
Escape. Live.
Let me guess...
so that I can make
the Dominion pay
for what they've done to you.
You wouldn't deny an old man
his revenge, would you?
I'll do as you ask
on one condition:
That you don't ask me this favor
as a mentor
or a superior officer...
but as a father asking his son.
You're not my son.
Father...
Father, you're dying.
For once in your life
speak the truth.
I should have killed your mother
before you were born.
You have always been a weakness
I can't afford.
So you've told me.
Many times.
Listen, Enabran...
all I ask
is that for this moment
let me be your son.
Elim...
remember that day
in the country...
you must have been almost five.
How can I forget it?
It was the only day.
I can still see you...
on the back
of that riding hound.
You must've fallen off
a dozen times.
But you never gave up.
I remember limping home.
You held my hand.
I was very proud of you...
that day.
Garak.
Gentlemen, I don't know
about you...
but my business here is done.
Then I suggest we find a way
out of here.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
A full-scale Dominion invasion
appears imminent.
Still, I remain confident
in my crew's ability
to face this crisis
as they have so many others...
with dedication
and with courage.
Our last listening post
in the Gamma Quadrant
just went dead.
That one was right
on the other side
of the wormhole.
Which means the Dominion fleet
is minutes away. Chief!
Nearly ready.
Worf...
Is a Klingon warrior.
He'll understand.
Neutrino levels in the wormhole
are rising.
If we're going to do this,
it's got to be now.
Ready.
Here goes nothing.
Activate graviton emitters.
May the Prophets forgive us.
We're losing it.
What happened?
Someone sabotaged
the emitter array.
Captain, the wormhole's opening.
Battle stations!