Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
One of our
listening posts
in the
Gamma Quadrant
picked this up
a few minutes ago.
It looks like
a Cardassian military code,
but the computer
doesn't recognize it.
It was a call for help...
from Enabran Tain.
We must warn the station.
There is only one reason
for the Dominion
to hide such a large fleet
this close to the wormhole.
You think they're planning
to attack the Alpha Quadrant?
There's no way
we can beat the Dominion.
Our only hope is
to prevent their fleet
from entering
the Alpha Quadrant.
You're going to destroy
the wormhole?
You have to trust me.
Things are going to change
on Cardassia.
What things?
I don't have
time to explain.
You're leaving now.
I can't go.
It's him, isn't it?!
That despicable tailor.
You don't want to leave
because you're waiting for him?
This is Internment Camp 371.
You are here because you
are enemies of the Dominion.
You're not my son.
Father, you're dying.
For once in your life,
speak the truth.
( groaning )
General Martok.
The changeling that replaced me
has caused the death
of countless Klingons.
It is a grave dishonor.
I can only imagine
what my replacement
is up to on the station.
( alarm beeping )
We're losing it.
What happened?
Someone sabotaged
the emitter array.
Battle stations!
( alarm blares )
And now the conclusion.
Release docking clamps.
Clamps released.
Shields up.
Power to phasers
and quantum torpedoes.
Weapons ready.
Bring us around.
Dukat's bird-of-prey
is in position.
Maintain communications
blackout.
Nobody fires until we have
our orders from Captain Sisko.
There sure are a lot of them.
That'll just make it
harder for us to miss.
They're still not
responding to our hails.
I think they're trying
to intimidate us.
It's working.
I don't believe it.
The Dominion ships are
turning away from the station.
They're laying in
a new course.
Heading?
Straight for Cardassia.
Dukat's ship
is breaking formation.
He's going after
the Dominion fleet.
Open a channel.
KIRA:
Dukat, stop trying
to be a hero.
Get back to the station.
Your concern
is touching, Major.
But I think you
misunderstand me.
I'm not attacking
the Dominion fleet.
I'm joining it.
What are you talking about?
I'm afraid I have
a confession
to make, Major.
For the past few months,
I've been conducting
secret negotiations
between the Dominion
and Cardassia.
And as of last week,
Cardassia has agreed
to become part of the Dominion.
You can't be serious.
Good-bye, Major.
You and I on the same side...
it never seemed quite...
right... did it?
Lock phasers.
Open fire.
Too late.
He's gone.
All clear.
The transmitter Tain used
to contact the station,
where is it?
You have to crawl
through that hole
and kind of slide your way
up into the wall.
It took him
over a year
to modify the old
life-support system
into a transmitter.
How did he operate it?
He wired the message
and the transmission
coordinates directly into
the system's circuitry.
That way, all
he had to do
was connect
the transmitter
to the power grid
and let it run.
Could the coordinates
and the message be changed?
You're planning
to contact the runabout.
We could activate
the transporter
and beam ourselves
onto the ship.
And run like hell.
Re-encoding
the transmitter won't be easy.
We'd have to reconfigure
the array
one circuit at a time.
Can you do it?
Me?
I'm no engineer.
Neither is Mr. Worf here.
You, on the other hand,
my dear Mr. Garak,
are a man of many
hidden talents.
Hmm.
If you
can't do it
nobody can.
It's nice to feel needed.
JEM'HADAR:
All prisoners
assemble immediately.
I repeat:
All prisoners
assemble immediately.
Who is that?
Deyos. The Vorta
that runs this camp.
No talking.
Touchy, aren't they?
All Cardassian prisoners
step forward.
I am pleased
to announce
that hostilities between
our peoples have ended.
As of today, Cardassia
has joined the Dominion.
Therefore, you're all
being sent home.
Congratulations on your new
status as Dominion citizens.
Not you, Mr. Garak.
Excuse me?
You're staying.
Well, there must be
some misunderstanding.
The last time I checked,
I was a Cardassian.
But not a very popular one,
I'm afraid.
At least not with the head
of the new Cardassian
government.
And who would that be?
Gul Dukat.
You might ask, should we fear
joining the Dominion?
And I answer you,
not in the least.
We should embrace
the opportunity.
The Dominion recognizes us
for what we are--
the true leaders
of the Alpha Quadrant.
And now that we are
joined together,
equal partners
in all endeavors,
the only people with anything
to fear will be our enemies.
My oldest son's birthday
is in five days.
To him and to Cardassians
everywhere,
I make the following pledge:
By the time his birthday dawns,
there will not be
a single Klingon alive
inside Cardassian territory,
or a single Maquis colony
left within our borders.
Cardassia will be made whole.
All that we have lost
will be ours again.
And anyone who stands in our way
will be destroyed.
This I vow
with my life's blood.
For my son...
for all our sons.
Somebody tell me
this is a bad dream.
It's no dream.
Well, I've got a vow
to make, too.
Next time I see Dukat,
I'm going to kill him.
Right now, we have a more
immediate concern,
such as-- who sabotaged
our graviton emitters?
I don't know who it was
but they did a pretty
thorough job.
The emitters had the
exact opposite effect
of what we'd intended.
They were supposed
to collapse
the wormhole's
spatial matrix
and close it forever.
Instead, they made the
matrix even more stable.
Not even trilithium explosives
could destroy it now.
So the Dominion
can send reinforcements
through the wormhole
whenever they want.
Looks like it's time
for another round
of blood screenings.
Obviously, we have
a changeling infiltrator
on the station.
What makes you think
it's a changeling?
That's who I'd send.
I think Julian's right.
Odo tells me that a Bajoran
maintenance engineer
has been missing
ever since
the Dominion fleet
arrived in the
Alpha Quadrant.
And if that was
our changeling,
he's either gone or
assumed a new identity.
We can't afford
to take any chances.
I want blood screenings
and phaser sweeps.
If he's out there,
we've got
to find him.
MARTOK:
He's taking too much time.
How long has he
been in there?
Close to an hour.
Garak, how's
it coming along?
I only wish I were still
a member of the Obsidian Order.
This would make a wonderful
interrogation chamber.
( popping )
Tight quarters.
No air, bad lighting,
random electric shocks.
It's perfect.
BASHIR:
Sounds like you're
enjoying yourself.
If you'd like, I'd happily
trade places with you.
I suppose you could
give me a crash course
in Cardassian field engineering.
I should be ready to take over
from you in what?
Five or six weeks?
Visitors.
Quiet.
It's time.
I am ready.
I've been looking forward
to this.
So have I.
Give me a hand.
Hold on, Garak.
Wait. The guards are
still too close.
Just a little while
longer, Garak.
I thought I would
be fighting Ikat'ika.
I would not
be so eager
if I were you.
This is
his handiwork.
He has much to answer for.
His time will come.
Now remember,
every time
you hit the ground,
you must touch
one of these posts
or else you
forfeit the match.
Today, we train
against a worthy adversary.
Observe, analyze, remember.
Soon we will face his people
in combat.
The lessons
you learn here
will ensure victory.
Victory is life!
ALL:
Begin!
( tone sounds )
Oh... come on.
( grunts of competition )
( tone sounds )
Clear.
Oh! That was
thoroughly unpleasant.
Are you all right?
I am fine.
It's just much hotter
in there than I thought.
I got a little
light-headed.
Give me a minute
and I'll go back in there.
No, you need more
than a minute.
Your pulse is racing.
I don't want to think
about your blood pressure.
Maybe you should wait
until tomorrow.
Do you want to get
off this hellhole?
You know I do.
Then let me
get back to work.
Rest.
For five minutes,
and from here on in,
you can take a 15-minute
break every hour.
Doctor's orders.
Was that the best
you have to offer?
He was our youngest
and least experienced.
I promise
your next opponent
will provide more
of a challenge.
View's even better
from Upper Pylon 2.
I keep hoping that
the wormhole will open.
That Garak's runabout
will come through,
and everything will
be all right again.
Maybe it will.
My father
says Garak's dead.
Right now, I wouldn't
believe your father
if he said rain was wet.
I used to think
my father was a hero.
That even when he
did something bad,
he had a good reason.
Everyone has their reasons.
That's what's so frightening.
People can find a way
to justify any action,
no matter how evil.
You think
my father is evil?
I think...
you can't judge people
by what they think...
or say...
only by what they do.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50564.2.
A large contingent
of Klingon warships
has arrived
from Cardassian space,
but its intentions,
at least for the moment,
remain unclear.
We're being hailed.
It's Chancellor Gowron.
He's requesting
permission to dock.
They've got wounded.
Permission granted.
I have the feeling
the Klingons' war
against the Cardassians
has taken a turn for the worse.
This is a dark day.
Not only
for the Klingon Empire,
but for the Alpha
Quadrant itself.
So what are we going
to do about it?
I will do
what must be done.
Fall back, pull my forces
out of Cardassian space,
fortify the Klingon Empire
and prepare for
a fight to the death.
Maybe there's
a better way.
The Khitomer Accords?
The treaty
between the Federation
and the Klingon Empire
is dead.
But we can bring it
back to life again.
This is the most
fortified position
between here
and the Klingon Empire.
There will be a Starfleet
task force here soon.
If you could
bring your fleet here--
Then we could
stand united
against the Dominion.
And if we do...
We might
have a chance.
( padd beeps )
Think of it.
Five years ago,
no one had ever heard
of Bajor or Deep Space 9,
and now,
all our hopes rest here.
Where the tides
of fortune take us,
no man can know.
They're tricky, those tides.
( console emitting
ticking beeps )
( grunting )
( bones crunch )
( guttural roar )
Five matches...
and five victories.
You truly have the spirit
of Kahless within you.
Until tomorrow.
I'll be waiting!
You've got
three broken ribs...
maybe four.
They will heal.
Not if you keep fighting,
they won't.
You're lucky you didn't
puncture a lung.
A body-- even
a Klingon body--
can only take
so much punishment.
I will fight.
It is the only
honorable thing to do.
He'll lose, and
in this condition,
he might even die.
Then I will die.
But I will not yield.
You heard him.
Bandage his ribs!
( ragged breathing )
I'm sorry, but that's
absolutely unacceptable.
I'm under enough strain
as it is.
I can't have you quitting on me.
Get a hold of yourself, Garak.
After all, you haven't had
one of these attacks in years.
Yes, this is
a tight, enclosed space.
Yes, there's not a lot
of room to move.
But a disciplined mind does not
allow itself to be sidetracked
by niggling psychological
disorders like...
claustrophobia.
Besides, this isn't
like Tzenketh.
The walls won't
collapse in on you.
Your friends are nearby.
There's plenty of air.
So there's nothing
to be concerned about.
( gasps )
Focus on the job.
You're the only person
who can contact the runabout.
People are depending on you.
Ziyal is depending on you.
You promised her
you'd come back,
and that young lady has had
quite enough disappointments
in her life without you
adding to them.
So...
control yourself.
You're stronger than this.
A disciplined mind....
I'm afraid that's
the best I can do.
Does it feel
any better?
Much better.
You're not a very
good liar, Mr. Worf.
( muffled bang )
What was that?
It's coming from
inside the wall.
Garak.
How long has he
been in there?
About half an hour.
Garak, Garak,
what is it?
Tell him to stop
before they hear him.
Garak, the panel's open now.
You can come out.
We've got to get him
out of there.
( softly ):
Garak.
( banging continues )
( grunts )
Garak, you
have to stop.
You're making
too much noise.
Garak!
( grunting )
The light...
the light went out.
I know.
Come on.
I think you can
take your break
a little early.
It would appear that he suffers
from an acute form
of claustrophobia.
It's a wonder that he lasted
as long as he did.
Then one of us
will have to finish
reconfiguring
the transmitter.
And who would you suggest
could do that?
Exactly.
If Garak can't
contact the runabout,
we're not
going anywhere.
The last of Gowron's ships
have arrived.
I'll have a repair crew
get to work on them
right away.
Any word
from Starfleet?
Admiral Gilhouly's
task force
is less than
four light-years away.
I'll feel a lot better
when they get here.
You're not
the only one.
KIRA:
Captain.
Yes, Major.
I just spoke with Odo.
Someone overrode
the security blocks
on the industrial replicator
on Level 17.
Sounds like our saboteur.
Did they catch him?
No such luck.
Do they know
what he replicated?
He wiped the memory core.
Tell Odo I want
all security details
to pull double shifts as of now.
If he wants more men,
have him talk to Gowron.
I'm sure the Chancellor
will be willing
to assign some Klingon troops
to guard key facilities.
Klingons helping
to protect Deep Space 9--
what an interesting concept.
These are
interesting times, Major.
DAX:
Captain.
Incoming message.
It's Gul Dukat.
In my office.
Dukat.
Please, Captain...
show a little respect--
you are talking to the head
of the Cardassian government.
I don't recognize
that government.
Your recognition
is irrelevant.
Well, if that's
what you think,
why are we having
this conversation?
Because the fact
is, Captain,
I feel a certain
obligation toward you.
After all, I freely admit,
you saved my life
on more than one occasion.
Don't remind me.
No, no, you should
be glad you did
because now I'm going
to return the favor...
and give you a chance to save
your precious Federation.
All you have to do
is convince them
to follow
Cardassia's example.
You expect us
to join the Dominion?
I expect you
to behave rationally.
Joining the Dominion
will save billions of lives,
and keep the Federation
from fading
into the mists of history.
By allowing it
to exist under Dominion rule?
No, thank you.
I'm afraid you'll like
the alternative even less.
Dukat, if you have something
to say to me, say it!
Then I'll make it simple.
A few days ago, I swore
all Cardassia lost
would be regained.
That space station
you're so fond of...
was built by Cardassia.
Funny, I thought it was built
by Bajoran slave labor.
Either surrender the station,
or I'll take it by force.
The choice is yours.
If you want to retake
this station, Dukat,
you are welcome to try.
Seven battles
and seven victories.
What hero of legend
could have done as well?
Heroes of legends
don't ache so much.
( chuckling ):
Your Federation friends
have taught you modesty,
but this is no time
for modesty.
When we return
to the Klingon Empire,
I will seek out Keedera himself
and tell him
of your glorious tale.
He will write a song
worthy of you.
Well, be sure to
send me a copy.
I'll do better
than that.
I can make sure
that he mentions you.
The healer that bound
the warrior's wounds,
so he could fight again.
Right now, the only part
of the song that I wish to hear
is the verse that tells
of our escape.
What good is defeating
every Jem'Hadar soldier
in this compound
if it does not bring us
closer to our freedom?
We have to come up with
a new escape plan.
GARAK:
That won't
be necessary.
The original one will work.
I just have to finish
what I started.
After all, a verse
about the Cardassian
who panicked
in the face of danger
would ruin
General Martok's song.
That would be
unfortunate.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
my dungeon awaits.
There is no greater enemy
than one's own fears.
It takes a brave
man to face them.
What can I do
for you, Chief?
Wasn't Lieutenant Japar
brought in here?
The Klingon engineer?
You just missed him.
The plasma burns weren't as bad
as they looked.
I better go find him.
I can't make head nor tail
of the power-relay systems
on his bird-of-prey.
We're never going to get
all these Klingon ships
up and running.
I have every confidence
in you, Chief.
Well, that makes all the
difference then, doesn't it?
How are Keiko and the kids?
They made it safely
to Bajor,
but I'm worried
about Molly.
She's getting old enough
to know when something's wrong.
I think she's scared.
It's only natural.
It'll pass.
Oh, by the way,
I ordered two sets
of those new duridium-alloy
darts I told you about.
They should be
here next week.
Darts?
We're facing a major
interstellar war,
and you're thinking about darts?
Well, life must go on.
Besides, I have a feeling
things are going to turn out
for the best.
I hope you're right.
Your asparagus
with yamok sauce.
The last of my fresh
asparagus, I might add.
Not that I'll need
to stock it anymore.
Somehow I get the feeling
there won't be much
demand for human food
once the Jem'Hadar have
finished with this place.
Aren't you being
a little pessimistic?
Am I?
The Jem'Hadar don't
eat, don't drink,
and they don't have sex,
and if that wasn't bad
enough, the Founders
don't eat and don't drink,
and they don't
have sex either.
Which, between you and me,
makes my financial future
less than promising.
It might not be so bad.
For all we know
the Vorta could be gluttonous,
alcoholic sex maniacs.
I never thought of that.
I wonder what their
favorite food is.
Good news.
The Starfleet task force
under Admiral Gilhouly
has entered Bajoran space.
Hope they know
what they're in for.
First, they demand
we come out here.
Then they make us wait.
They are worthy fighters,
but they have
no sense of honor.
Is there no Jem'Hadar
willing to face me?
Fascinating.
Even after all
he's been through,
the Klingon still
thirsts for battle.
Doesn't he ever
tire of it?
I never do.
You fight because that
is what you were
designed to do.
All that motivates him
is some barbaric
sense of honor.
And that is something
you will never understand.
Prepare yourself.
I've found you
a worthy opponent.
Where is he?
Right in front of you.
Victory is life.
Today is a good day to die.
( grunts )
Tain, I don't know
if you can hear me.
But if you can,
I just want you to know
you may not have been
much of a father,
but I really wish
you were alive right now.
That way, you could be in here
instead of me.
( grunts )
Jem'Hadar.
Can we get him out?
No time.
The Cardassian--
where is he?
Outside...
I suppose.
He is not outside.
Move.
What do you want with him?
JEM'HADAR:
He is to be
put to death.
Sir!
If you wish to live,
explain this.
The Bird-of-Prey Y'tem
is in position.
That's everybody.
Major. Commander.
Report to the Defiant.
Yes, sir.
Good luck.
To all of us.
Deploy the runabouts.
O'BRIEN:
Runabout Yukon,
prepare for departure.
Runabouts Rio Grande
and Volga, stand by.
FEMALE VOICE:
Yukon ready.
Engines engaged.
O'BRIEN:
Good luck, Yukon.
Sir, I'm picking up
a large tachyon buildup.
Multiple vectors.
Ships de-cloaking.
Romulans.
They're requesting permission
to join the fleet.
I'll be damned.
Permission granted.
KIRA:
Defiant to Ops.
Go ahead, Major.
Sensors have just detected
Dominion and Cardassian ships
entering Bajoran space.
ETA ten minutes.
I'll ask you for the last
time-- what is this?
It's either
a self-sealing stem bolt
or a reverse-ratchetting
router.
I'm just not sure.
She is next.
JEM'HADAR:
Sir!
If you'll allow me...?
( grunts )
Worf...
honor has been satisfied.
Stay down.
Finish this.
( grunts )
What do you see?
I see nothing.
It's dark.
My people have a saying:
Never turn your back
on a Breen.
Doctor, would you keep
the noise down?
I'm trying to work in here.
Garak, how many transtator
circuits have you got left?
Three.
Well, work fast,
because pretty soon
we're going to be up
to our necks in Jem'Hadar.
( grunting )
Enough, Klingon.
You have proven
your worth.
Worf...
you heard him.
Enough.
I will not yield!
What are you waiting for?
End this.
It's over.
It is not over.
You heard him.
( gasps )
I yield.
You what?
I yield!
I cannot defeat
this Klingon.
All I can do is kill him,
and that no longer
holds my interest.
Shoot them both.
Got it!
BASHIR:
Take him to one of
the cabins in the back.
I'll be with you
as soon as I can.
Garak.
You did well.
So did you.
BASHIR:
Take us
to maximum warp, Garak.
We've got to get
a message to the station.
The Dominion fleet
should be in visual range.
On screen.
Where are they?
According
to their warp signatures,
they should be right there.
Some kind of cloaking device?
I didn't know
the Dominion had them.
Or the Cardassians,
for that matter.
I'm picking up
additional warp signatures
bearing 183 mark 97.
244 mark 12.
302 mark 133.
KIRA:
Defiant to Ops.
Go ahead.
According
to our sensor readings,
there are Dominion ships
all around us,
but we can't see them or get
any kind of targeting lock.
We're reading the same thing.
They're everywhere.
What are your orders, Captain?
Chief!
I need targets!
I'm trying,
but I can't get anything.
We may have to wait for them
to open fire and then--
( console beeping )
Captain, I'm picking up
a priority one message
from the Gamma Quadrant.
It's Dr. Bashir!
Bashir?
Computer, locate Dr. Bashir.
Dr. Bashir is not
on the station.
What was
his last known location?
Dr. Bashir's last known location
was Runabout Pad E.
Sisko to Defiant.
Go ahead.
Major, you have new orders.
I want you to find
the Yukon and destroy it
at any cost.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Commander.
The Yukon is headed straight
for the Bajoran sun.
Its shields are holding.
How can that be?
Looks like someone's been doing
some modifications to the Yukon.
I'm also picking up
large amounts of trilithium,
tekasite and protomatter
on board.
A bomb.
If it explodes
inside the sun...
It could trigger
a supernova--
wipe out the entire
fleet, the station...
And Bajor.
We have to use
the tractor beams.
We're too far away.
Want to bet?
Take us to warp.
Inside a solar system?!
If we don't, there won't
be a solar system left.
( ticking beeps )
The runabout's been destroyed.
If the sun had gone nova,
it would have wiped out
the Dominion fleet, too.
Chief, scan for
those warp signatures again.
Captain...
They're gone, aren't they?
All I'm reading is
normal background radiation.
The warp signatures
must have been faked.
The Dominion's real fleet
never left Cardassian space.
This was all an elaborate trap--
an attempt to destroy
the station and Bajor,
and cripple the Federation
and Klingon fleets,
without ever firing a shot.
Tell our friends out there
to stand down.
Armageddon will have to wait
for another day.
Ziyal?
I told you I'd be back.
( gasps )
I never doubted it.
O'BRIEN:
Four weeks?
Are you telling me
I've been hanging around
with a changeling
for over a month?
And you never even suspected
it wasn't me?
No, and the worst part is,
the clues were right
in front of me.
What clues?
Well, for one thing,
he was a lot easier
to get along with.
( sighs )
So, I suppose
this means you want
your Klingon opera
collection back.
Intact.
More or less.
GOWRON:
Then it's settled.
In light of the new treaty,
and the continued
Dominion threat
to the Alpha Quadrant
there will be a permanent
Klingon military presence
on this station.
But I choose the Commander.
Agreed.
Mr. Worf thinks very highly
of you, General.
I think very highly of him.
Then I can't think
of a better man for the job,
if you'll take it.
I would be honored.
KIRA:
Ops to Sisko.
Sisko here.
You're receiving
an incoming message.
It's from Dukat.
Well, Captain,
I must congratulate you.
If that protomatter device
had gone off inside the sun...
Well... the death toll
would have been enormous.
And your daughter
would have been
one of the casualties.
Ziyal made her choice.
As far as I'm concerned,
she's no longer my daughter.
You know, Dukat,
I thought you'd changed
in the last five years.
I see I was wrong.
One man's villain
is another man's hero, Captain.
You should see the monument
they're erecting in my honor
at the gateway
to the Imperial Plaza.
Is that why you sold out
your people to the Dominion?
For a monument?!
What I did...
I did to make Cardassia
strong again.
And mark my words, Captain,
I succeeded.
You may have escaped defeat
this day,
but tomorrow--
We will see about tomorrow.
Yes, we will.