Okay, that's 12 spins,
and not a single dabo
so far.
The pot is growing
and someone's going
to be a big winner...
Today's the day,
Brother.
I'm really going
to do it this time.
You've been saying
that for weeks.
I've been waiting
for the right moment,
and this is it.
Now?
It's perfect.
She's about to go on a break,
and when she does,
she'll come over here
and say hi to me,
like she always does,
and that's when I'll do it.
Okay, let's hear it.
I... uh...
Leeta, would you like...
maybe... to...
one night...
soon... to... maybe...?
Rom.
You're a regular poet.
I can do better.
Prove it.
Hi, Rom.
Hello, Leeta.
Bye.
( sighing )
I must be doing
something wrong.
I don't know, Leeta.
Maybe he's just not
interested in you.
Well, I know he likes me.
Likes you, yes, but
he's an engineer.
A problem solver.
He needs a woman with
a body and brains.
I have brains.
Sure you do, honey.
That's why I hired you.
Now, eat up, and then
take those brains
back to the
dabo wheel,
where the customers can get
a good, long look at them.
( dartboard beeps )
BASHIR:
Triple 20!
Oh, he's back
in the zone today.
I never really left it.
Just been giving you
a chance
to get even.
Thank you,
but I don't need your charity.
Another game?
Maybe one.
I promised Molly
I'd do some coloring
with her this afternoon.
With all this attention
focused on the baby,
I don't want her
to start feeling
that we've forgotten
about her.
A father's work
is never done.
You said it.
Still, it's worth it.
You should give it
a try sometime.
Me? No.
Why not?
I bet you'd make
a great father.
I'm not exactly a family type.
MAN:
Dr. Bashir,
I presume?
That's me.
I'm Louis Zimmerman
director of holographic imaging
and programming
at the Jupiter Research Station,
and I'm here to make you...
immortal.
You're familiar, of course,
with the Emergency
Medical Holographic program.
I've heard of it.
It's a hologram designed
to provide assistance
during emergencies
in Sick Bay.
It does much more than
provide assistance.
A holographic doctor
can literally replace
a starship's medical officer
during an emergency.
I'm surprised you don't
have one on the station.
The station facilities
are Cardassian in origin.
Most of our equipment
is incompatible
with Federation technology.
How unfortunate for you.
In any case, the
original EMH program
was designed for
short-term use only
but now Starfleet
has requested a program
designed to operate
as a full-time doctor.
Full time?
You're not talking
about replacing real doctors?
No, no, of course not.
Why is everyone so worried
about holograms taking
over the universe?
There are many situations
where a holo-doctor
could be more beneficial
than a humanoid.
Research outposts,
subspace communication
stations,
long-range exploratory
vessels.
In short, anywhere
that life support,
or living space
is at a premium
and where the
primary mission
does not require the
doctor to leave Sick Bay.
I see.
And they want to model
this new EMH program
after Dr. Bashir.
Technically, it
is an LMH--
long-term medical
holographic program.
And, yes, Starfleet Medical
has selected Dr. Bashir
to provide
the template.
Who was the template
for the EMH?
Me.
It was my program
after all.
It only seemed logical
to use myself as a model.
Of course.
This must be quite an honor.
Yes, it... is
quite a feather in my cap, sir.
It is nothing less than
a shot at immortality.
The original EMH program
will probably
still be in use
for decades to come.
The LMH will undoubtedly
last far longer than that.
That is, if I can work out
certain technical problems.
Now, I'll need
to remain here
for at least
three weeks.
I'll need quarters,
access to your main computer,
a technician to
install my equipment,
a high-speed data
link with my lab--
Doctor, my First Officer,
Major Kira
will see
to all your needs.
Congratulations,
Doctor.
I know I speak
for everyone on the station
when I say we're really
very proud of you.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Let's go.
BASHIR:
This is a long
questionnaire.
ZIMMERMAN:
I pride myself
on my attention to detail.
Let's see...
"compare and contrast
"your eating habits
at age five
"with those of ten,
15, 20 and 25."
ZIMMERMAN:
It will be necessary
for the holo-doctor
to interact naturally
with patients for weeks,
possibly even months.
The doctor will be expected
to share amusing anecdotes,
extend sympathy,
swap dirty jokes,
and even have
culinary opinions
formed by experience.
You mean this program
is going to include
all his personal
likes and dislikes?
That is why we bother to choose
a human template
in the first place.
O'BRIEN:
Wow. Think
of it, Julian.
If this thing works,
you'll be able to irritate
hundreds of people
you've never even met.
( laughs )
If you two could suspend
your oh-so-amusing banter
for the moment,
I'd like to begin
the optical parameter scans.
What do you want me to do?
Just stand there
and look like a doctor.
If you can.
Dabo!
We don't have
anything like this
on Jupiter Station.
Or like her.
She's beautiful,
isn't she?
Who is she?
Her name's Leeta.
My ex-girlfriend.
Who broke it off?
She did.
Oh. I like her
already.
I think I'll have
to add her name
to my list
of interviews.
Interviews?
I'll be conducting
in-depth interviews
with your friends,
colleagues, family members,
in order to build
a more rounded
psychological profile
for the LMH.
I see.
Well, regarding
my family members, um...
would you refrain from--
ODO:
Excuse me
for interrupting, Doctor.
Doctor.
The Antidean transport
wishes to leave
the station a day early.
Their cargo is still
under quarantine.
If you could issue
a health certificate...
Now?
It would expedite matters.
All right. Um...
I'll meet you in Cargo Bay 3
in ten minutes.
Thank you, Doctor.
Doctor.
Well, duty calls.
I wonder if you
could do me a favor
and consider
not interviewing my parents?
Why?
Well, to be blunt, um...
we're not close,
and we haven't been
for many years,
and I would consider it
a personal favor
if you would sort of
leave my parents out of it.
I see.
Well, I certainly
understand.
Well, thank you.
Um... I-I'll see you
tomorrow.
Hmm.
Note: Contact subject's parents
immediately.
ZIMMERMAN:
Computer, activate
LMH Test Program 1.
Does it meet
with your... approval?
Yeah, it looks all right.
Except for the eyes--
they seem a little dead.
They don't have
that certain sparkle...
the zest for life
that greets me
in the mirror
every morning.
( sighs )
This is a test run.
I can assure you that
the final product will be...
"zesty."
Does it talk?
Not yet.
First, I have to load the LMH
with the basic database
and software configurations
of the original program.
Computer.
Activate the EMH.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
This is a level-3
diagnostic.
I understand.
Diagnostics look good.
Beginning
data transferal.
Data transferal?
Am I being replaced?
You're being supplemented
by a new long-term program.
By him?
ZIMMERMAN:
There.
Transfer's complete.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Well, that's original.
He doesn't even look old
enough to be a doctor.
If you'd
like my advice,
you should delete
this program.
Now that I'm here,
why would you need
an archaic piece
of software like him?
Archaic?
We can discuss this
at another time.
Listen--
He doesn't sound
much like me.
I'm sorry.
Too zesty for you?
Actually, he sounds
more like you.
As I said,
I've loaded the LMH
with the basic EMH
software package.
We'll have to build
a new set of algorithms
based on your
scintillating personality.
I hope you're
more interesting
than you seem.
I'd hate to be boring.
There may be
no preventing that.
But we'll see
what his friends have to say.
ZIMMERMAN:
What were your initial
impressions of Dr. Bashir?
Good and bad.
Young, eager, ambitious.
He was fresh out
of medical school.
Looking forward
to his first taste
of "frontier medicine."
Sometimes, he let
that natural impulse
override his sense of decorum.
You mean he was...
difficult.
No, but sometimes he could...
well, give you
way too much information.
Could you
elaborate on that?
Sometimes, he just...
didn't know when to shut up.
Are you implying
he harassed you
with unwanted
advances?
No, but he was
very persistent.
I see.
Could you be
more specific?
You're not being
very helpful.
I do not like doctors.
Any doctors.
You can rest assured
that I will keep
anything you say
in the strictest
confidence.
You're sure about that?
I wouldn't want this
to get back to Julian.
You have my word.
Well, the truth is,
he's... an extraordinary person.
A real sense of honor
and integrity...
great sense of humor...
warm, caring...
You're sure
he's not going to read this?
Positive.
So, is that all?
Uh... there is
one other thing.
Would you have dinner
with me this evening?
WOMAN:
Oh, well, that I'm
not going to tell you--
MAN:
Well, I think
you should--
WOMAN 2:
Times like this, I think
I'm the happiest person--
MAN 2:
Stroll along the promenade--
LEETA:
You want a real
game, try dom-jot.
If I ran this place,
we'd have three
dom-jot tables
and two prayko alleys.
And I'd make sure
the customers
had a lot more fun.
Quark is a lot of things,
but he's not fun.
I'm fun.
I bet you are.
You're a fascinating
woman, Leeta.
For a dabo girl.
ZIMMERMAN:
Not at all.
You're charming,
intelligent,
witty...
and extraordinarily
beautiful.
Thank you.
ROM:
Excuse me!
I need to talk to you.
It's very important.
All right.
Will you excuse me?
Of course.
What is it, Rom?
I want to ask you if you...
I want to...
I... oh...
I wanted to ask if...
tomorrow morning
would be a good time
for me to fix
your replicator.
Oh.
Sure.
That would be fine.
Okay.
Tomorrow morning, then.
Enjoy the rest
of your evening.
Thanks.
I'm a little concerned
about the amount of argonite
that's seeping into
the station's air supply.
17 parts per million.
That's well within
safety margins.
Yes, but it's on the rise,
and I'd like to--
I'm sorry to interrupt, sir,
but there are a couple of
visitors here looking for Julian
and I thought he might
want to see them
right away.
Well, send them in.
Oh...
my God.
Hello, Jules.
Uh, Captain...
allow me to introduce
Amsha and...
Richard Bashir,
my parents.
I'm Captain Benjamin Sisko.
Welcome to Deep Space 9.
Thank you, Captain.
It's a pleasure to finally see
where Jules works.
We wanted to come before,
but my schedule's
been so busy up until now.
I'm sure you know
what it's like.
SISKO:
All too well,
I'm afraid.
What is it you do,
Mr. Bashir?
Oh... I've done many things.
At the moment, I'm involved
in landscape architecture,
designing public spaces,
parks mostly.
I love the idea of
working on projects
that thousands of
people will enjoy
long after I'm gone.
They're my... my legacy,
my gift to succeeding
generations.
Aside from Jules
here, of course.
You must be very
proud of your son.
Oh, yes.
He's a very...
gifted young man.
I hope you're putting
all his talents
to good use, Captain.
We try.
Well, sometimes
you have to push
him a little.
It took quite a while
to talk him into
taking up medicine.
But he did.
So you're the reason
he went to medical school.
That's right.
He wanted to become--
Perhaps we should save that
until another time, Richard.
I'm sure the Captain
is a very busy man.
Oh...
of course.
Maybe after our
interviews are over.
Interviews?
Yes, with a Dr.
um... Zimmerman.
Didn't he tell you?
No, he didn't.
He said it was urgent.
That the two of you
were working together
on a very important project,
and that we had to
come here right away.
Yes.
Well, why don't I see
if I can find you some
accommodations for this evening.
Yeah.
It was a pleasure
to meet you both.
I hope we get a chance
to see you again.
I can't wait
to hear some stories
about Julian
as a little boy.
Oh, lord,
there are so many.
You know, from the time
he was this high,
we knew he was destined
for greatness.
The captain, Father,
is a very busy man.
We'll talk later.
( chuckling )
Oh, we're just
working out a few bugs.
Chief, if you'll
excuse us,
I'd like a moment or two
alone with Dr. Zimmerman.
Of course.
You brought my parents
to this station
against my explicit wishes
that you keep them
out of this project.
I'm sorry it upsets you,
but their input is--
You had no right
to bring them here.
I did not bring
them here.
I simply issued
an invitation.
You said it was urgent.
It is urgent-- to me.
Like it or not,
they're an important
part of your background
and I need
to interview them.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a delivery to make.
( door chimes )
Have I caught you
at a bad time?
It's never a bad time
for flowers.
Come on in.
Could you find a place
for those while I change?
Of course.
By the way, if you're
trying to impress me...
you've succeeded.
I spoke to some of my colleagues
at the Jupiter Station
this morning.
It seems that the manager
of our station café
has decided to quit.
Really?
They're still looking
for a new manager.
Someone with experience
in both food service
and entertainment.
Someone like you.
Me?
Y-yes. I've already
taken the liberty
of speaking to our station's
commanding officer about you,
and she's amenable to the idea.
The café is yours
if you want it.
My own café?
Oh.
Sorry.
Not at all.
It's not very big.
Less than half the size
of Quark's.
Really?
But there's room enough
for a couple of dom-jot tables.
But I've never run a restaurant
or any kind of business.
I barely even know
how to tend bar.
That puts you one step ahead
of our last bartender.
But where would I stay?
I don't even know anybody there.
You know me...
and I was hoping you would
consider staying with me.
But Louis...
I just met you.
I mean, I like you--
You see? You're warming up
to me already.
Given time,
you might begin to feel more.
Just as I do.
Besides, you said
you liked cerebral men,
and, at the risk
of sounding immodest,
I have a towering intellect.
Come with me, Leeta.
Please.
I promise
you won't regret it.
I know I won't.
I need to think about that.
Take all the time you need.
Captain Sisko seems
like a very nice man, Jules.
Not like the Captain
of the transport
that brought us here.
I've never met a ruder,
more abrasive man in my life.
I tell you, when I
used to run shuttles,
I never would've tolerated
that kind of behavior
towards my passengers.
Dad, you're talking
to me now.
You were
a third-class steward
for all of six months.
That's right...
and I was required
to have daily contact
with the passengers.
And you can bet that if I even
looked at them the wrong way,
I would've been discharged
on the spot.
I thought you were.
No.
I resigned.
Are you still doing research,
Jules?
Yes. Right now, I'm working
on two studies
of prion replication
in ganglionic cell clusters.
You could've done research
back on Earth.
I told you that five years ago.
But you insisted
on taking this position
because you wanted to work in,
um... frontier medicine.
On DS9, I can do both.
So, you're doing
"landscape architecture" now.
It's all he can talk about.
You should see the stacks
of drawings in our house.
It's like living
in a drafting studio.
Some, uh, very important people
have expressed interest
in my park designs.
I have some very good prospects
on the horizon.
Oh, you always have
very good prospects
and they were always
just over that horizon.
Um... maybe you should tell us
about the interviews
we're doing tomorrow, Jules.
What kind of questions
will they ask?
Well, Dr. Zimmerman,
as I understand it,
is trying to compile a complete
psychological profile of me.
He's going to be asking you
all sorts of questions.
Try to keep your answers
as brief
and to the point
as you can.
You don't want to give him
any openings
to probe into any...
awkward areas.
I'm sure we can handle it.
Try not to take this
too lightly.
He's going to be asking detailed
questions about my childhood,
and if you're
not careful--
You don't trust us?
He didn't say
that, Richard.
No, but that's what he meant,
isn't it?
You think we're
going to slip up,
say the wrong thing,
get us all in trouble?
Look, I've got
a lot at stake here.
My whole career
could be destroyed
if Dr. Zimmerman gets wind
of our little secret.
You've got a lot at stake?
Well, what about us?
We could go
to prison, Jules.
Have you ever thought
about that?
Of course I've thought
about that!
That's why I want you
to take this seriously!
Ah, so now we're not
taking it seriously.
We're not as bright as he is.
We don't have
your gifted intellect
so we can't see
the perfectly obvious.
This is exactly why I haven't
been home in three years.
Jules, please--
No, let him go.
He can barely stand to be
in the same room
with us!
( door closes )
( sighs )
I haven't made up my mind, yet.
I mean, this could be
a big opportunity,
but that's no reason
to rush into anything.
What do you think I should do?
I...
I don't know.
( sighing )
If I had a reason to stay,
I'd stay.
Do I have a reason to stay?
I...
I don't know.
Well, I...
guess I better take the job.
Great.
Is that all you can say?
I...
I--
You don't know.
Thanks, Rom.
You've been a big help.
You're welcome.
Is there something
I can do for you?
Your father has something
he wants to say.
Richard?
( clearing throat )
It's a... stressful time
for all of us,
and maybe I said some things
I... shouldn't have.
AMSHA:
What he's trying
to say is
we would never do anything
to jeopardize your career.
And just so there's
no misunderstanding,
I give you my word
that, at no time
in our interview
with Dr. Zimmerman
will we ever mention,
or even hint at the fact
that you were genetically
enhanced as a child.
AMSHA:
Jules, you can trust us.
Your father and I
kept the secret of
your DNA resequencing
for almost 25 years
and we're not going
to let it out now.
RICHARD:
But I would just add
that, despite what
the authorities
would like us to believe,
genetic engineering is nothing
to be ashamed of.
You're not any less human
than anyone else.
In fact,
you're a little more.
We didn't come here
to start another fight.
Let's just try to
get through this.
All right?
All right.
Who are those people?
( sighing )
I can't believe
you set them up like that!
We didn't set them up.
They just happened to walk in
while the program
was running.
Zimmerman thought it
would be a good idea
to test the
program's ability
to cope with an
unexpected situation.
And you let them go on?
You let them stand there
and make fools of themselves
while the two of you
sat in the back room
and laughed?!
Look, I'm sorry about this.
I wish it had never happened.
But it has, and now
we've got a problem.
I don't want to talk about it.
Julian, Zimmerman
is going to file a report
saying that
Dr. Bashir
is unsuitable
for computer modeling
because of his suspected
genetically enhanced background.
Do you know what's going
to happen when that report
gets back to
Starfleet Medical?
There's going to be
a formal investigation.
Which will lead
to my eventual dismissal
from the service.
Then it's true?
You're...
The word you're looking for
is "unnatural,"
meaning "not from nature."
"Freak"
or "monster"
would also be acceptable.
I was six.
Small for my age, a bit
awkward, physically
not very bright.
In the first grade
when the other children
were learning
how to read and write
and use the computer,
I was still trying
to tell a dog from a cat
and a tree from a house.
I didn't really understand
what was happening.
I knew that I wasn't doing
as well as my classmates.
There were so many concepts
that they took for granted
that... I couldn't
begin to master,
and I didn't know why.
All I knew... was that I
was a great disappointment
to my parents.
I don't remember when
they made the decision,
but just before
my seventh birthday...
we left Earth
for Adigeon Prime.
At first, I remember
being really excited
at seeing all the
aliens in the hospital,
and then they gave me a room
and... began the treatments,
and my entire world
began to change.
What were
the treatments?
Some kind
of DNA recoding?
( sighing )
The technical term
is "accelerated critical
neural pathway formation."
Over the course of
the next two months,
my genetic structure
was manipulated
to accelerate the growth
of neuronal networks
in my cerebral cortex
and a whole new
Julian Bashir
was born.
In what way did they...
change you?
Well, my mental abilities
were top priority, of course.
My IQ jumped five points a day
for over two weeks.
Followed by improvements
in my hand/eye coordination,
stamina, vision, reflexes,
weight, height.
In the end, everything
but my name
was altered in some way.
When we returned
to Earth,
we even moved to
a different city.
I was enrolled
in a new school
using falsified records
my parents obtained
somewhere.
Instead of being
the slowest learner,
I was the star pupil.
And no one ever suspected?
Oh, there's no stigma
attached to success, Chief.
After the treatments,
I never looked back,
but the truth is, I'm a fraud.
You're not a fraud.
I don't care
how many enhancements
your parents had done.
Genetic recoding
can't give you ambition
or a personality or compassion
or any of the things
that make a person truly human.
Well, Starfleet Medical
won't see it that way.
DNA resequencing for any reason
other than repairing serious
birth defects is illegal.
Any genetically enhanced
human being
is barred from serving
in Starfleet
or practicing medicine.
I don't think
there's been a case
dealing with any of this
in a hundred years.
You can't be sure
how they'll react.
Oh, I am sure.
Once the truth comes out,
I'll be cashiered
from the service.
It's that simple.
There must be
something we can do.
We can't just give up.
There is something I can do.
Resign
before Dr. Zimmerman
files his report.
Oh, Julian--
It's over, Miles.
I always knew this could happen.
Now it has.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'd like to be alone.
( sighs )
I should have told her
how I felt.
Thank the Nagus
that you didn't.
Remember what happened
with Nog's mother?
Yeah...
don't want to think
about her, do you?
Let me refresh
your memory.
You signed a standard
five-year marriage contract
with Prinadora's father
because you wanted
to have a child--
a simple everyday
business deal.
But then, you fell in love
with your wife,
and wanted to extend
the contract.
And you were so in love
that you never bothered
to read the extension
before signing it.
So, in the end,
her father swindled you
out of all of your money.
Prinadora left you
for a richer man.
And you got stuck
with Nog.
Hooray for romance.
Leeta is not Prinadora.
She's a female, Rom,
and the one constant
in the universe is
females are trouble.
Look, if you're lonely...
I've got
a new holosuite program.
"Vulcan Love Slave:
Part Two--
The Revenge."
Give it a try.
After a couple hours...
you'll forget
all about Leeta.
We're not going to just
take this lying down,
that's for sure.
I'll arrange for legal counsel.
We're going to fight this
all the way
to the Federation
Supreme Court.
We can't fight this.
You better change that attitude
right now
if you want to hang on
to your career.
Jules, listen
to your father.
He's trying
to help you.
Neither of you
is listening to me.
I don't want to drag this
through the courts.
We're a little
beyond worrying
about your wants, Jules.
We have a serious problem here
and we have to stop the whining
and concentrate
on coming up with a new plan.
A new plan.
Yes!
Let's come up with a new plan!
That's the way we do things
in this family, isn't it?
We don't face our problems.
We come up with new plans.
Don't like your job?
Well, move along
to the next one.
Don't like the law?
Well, find a way
to get around it.
But whatever you do,
do not accept responsibility.
All those gifts...
all those accomplishments...
and you still want to behave
like a spoiled child.
Well, you better grow up
right now
or you're going
to lose everything.
You mean, you're going
You're going to lose
your only
real accomplishment
in this life--
me.
You said before,
I'm your legacy,
your proud gift to the world.
Well, Father, your gift
is about to be revealed...
as a fraud.
Just like you.
I'm still your father, Jules,
and I will not have you
talk to me like that.
No.
You used to be my father.
Now... you're my architect.
The man who designed
a better son
to replace the defective one
he was given.
Well, your design...
has a built-in flaw.
It's illegal.
You're so smart.
You know so much you can
sit there and judge us,
but you're still
not smart enough to see
that we saved you from a life
of remedial education
and underachievement!
You don't know that.
You didn't give me a chance.
You were
falling behind.
I was six years old.
You decided
I was a failure
in the first grade.
You don't understand, Jules.
You never did.
No, you don't understand!
I stopped calling myself
Jules when I was 15,
and I'd found out
what you'd done to me.
I'm Julian!
What difference
does that make?!
It makes every difference!
Because I'm different!
Can't you see?!
Jules Bashir died
in that hospital
because you couldn't
live with the shame
of having a son
who didn't measure up!
That's not true.
We were never
ashamed of you-- never.
I'm sorry, Mother,
but the truth is--
You don't know.
You've never had a child.
You don't know what it's like
to watch your son...
to watch him fall a little
further behind every day.
You know he's trying,
but something's
holding him back.
You don't know what it's like
to stay up every night
worrying that maybe
it's your fault.
Maybe you did something wrong
during the pregnancy,
or maybe you weren't
careful enough,
or maybe there's something wrong
with you.
Maybe you passed on
a genetic defect
without even knowing it.
Amsha...
No, this is important.
You can condemn us
for what we did.
You can say
it's illegal or immoral
or whatever you want
to say...
but you have
to understand
that we didn't do it
because we were ashamed...
but because
you were our son,
and we loved you.
What do you want us to do?
Nothing.
I'm going to visit Captain Sisko
in the morning
and explain
the situation to him,
and tender
my Starfleet resignation.
Are you certain
this is what you want?
Yes.
I just... want to leave
the station quietly.
( door opens, closes )
Come in, Doctor.
We were just
talking about you.
Admiral, allow me
to introduce
Dr. Julian Bashir.
Doctor, this is
Rear Admiral Bennett,
Judge Advocate General.
Admiral.
Doctor.
May I ask
what's going on?
Your parents came
to see me this morning.
They explained the situation
about your genetic background.
I contacted Admiral Bennett
a short time ago.
BENNETT:
We've just reached
an agreement
which will allow you
to retain
both your commission
and your medical practice.
I'm going to prison.
What?!
Two years.
It's a minimum security penal
colony in New Zealand.
You can't do this.
BENNETT:
It was your father's
suggestion, Doctor.
He pleads guilty
to illegal genetic engineering
and in exchange,
you stay in the service.
Well, I want
no part of it.
I'm not going to stand
here while my father--
Jules...
Julian.
Listen to me.
This is my decision.
I'm the one who took you
to Adigeon Prime.
I'm the one who should, uh...
take responsibility for it.
Let him do this, Julian.
Two years?
Isn't that a bit harsh?
BENNETT:
I don't think so.
200 years ago,
we tried to improve the species
through DNA resequencing.
And what did we get
for our trouble?
The Eugenics Wars.
For every Julian Bashir
that can be created,
there's a Khan Singh
waiting in the wings--
a superhuman--
whose ambition
and thirst for power
have been enhanced
along with his intellect.
The law
against genetic engineering
provides a firewall
against such men,
and it's my job
to keep that firewall intact.
I've made my offer.
Do you accept?
Yes.
Then report to my office
at Starfleet Headquarters
once you arrive on Earth.
( whispers ):
Take your time.
Good-bye, Julian.
Good-bye, Mother.
Well... I guess I'll see you
in a couple of years.
Oh, I'm sure
they have, uh...
visiting hours
at your facility.
Maybe I could--
That would be
most welcome.
Father.
Thank you.
Here, just think--
I may usher in
a new renaissance
in landscape
architecture.
I'll certainly have time
to work on my designs.
( distant wailing yell )
Do you hear something?
What is that?
It's getting closer.
ROM ( yelling ):
Wait!
Wait.
We heard you
the first time.
Leeta...
don't go.
Why not?
Because...
I love you.
And I want you
to stay.
I love you, too, Rom.
Oh.
Doctor...
I'm... sorry.
No. Don't be.
True love should
always win.
I'm... happy for you.
Really.
You're a sweet, wonderful
and brilliant man.
There's someone out there
for you, Doctor.
I know it.
I don't think so.
Perhaps I'm
better suited
to a life of
solitary research.
And dedication
to my chosen field of study.
Don't worry about me.
I'll be fine.
Good-bye.
Bye.
Excuse me,
are you familiar
with the ancient text
known as the Kama Sutra?
You remind me of an etching...
ALL:
Dabo!
( cheering )
Oh, not my day.
Not your week.
You know what,
Chief?
I never got a chance
to thank you
for what you said--
Ah. None of that.
Especially not
in the middle of a game.
Ooh. Yes!
Looks like it's
your game again.
What's that?
Five in a row?
At least.
Wait a minute.
You haven't been letting
me win, have you?
What makes you think that?
You said your hand/eye
coordination
had been
genetically enhanced.
Well, maybe I have been
letting you win...
a little bit.
I don't believe it.
I don't need you
to patronize me.
I can... play
at your level.
I never said
you couldn't.
Well, play then.
Really play.
( dartboard beeping )
All right.
From now on...
you play from over here.
I play from up here.
And if that doesn't work...
we'll try a blindfold.