Computer. Time.
1821 hours.
Can I help you?
I think so.
What are you doing?
Where is it?
Where is what?
I don't even know
what you're looking for.
Yes, you do.
Well?
It's not here.
That's not good.
Is it possible we
have the wrong man?
It's starting to look that way.
This is very embarrassing.
Now, listen to me.
We know why you're here
we know who you came to meet
and we know what you
are going to give her.
So for the last time,
where is it?
All right...
I'll take you to it.
You see?
It was him all along.
I thought it was on stun.
Huh.
Hmm.
Look what you did
to the carpet.
What do we do now?
We don't have time
to search the whole station.
We wait for the woman.
She might know
where he hid it.
You wanted to see us?
Is that the new
holosuite program?
Queen's Gambit.
It came this morning.
Finally... that friend of yours
promised to send it
two months ago.
According to Felix,
it's worth the wait.
He said it's the most elaborate
program he's ever designed.
What parts do we get to play?
Well, you get to play
Lady Wantsomore
a beautiful socialite
who's brainwashed
to assassinate
the Queen of England.
Ooh... somebody stop me.
What about me?
Odo plays Nigel Dunlap
a former agent
who comes out of retirement
to help me foil
this diabolical plot.
Perfect.
And I play...
Julian, we know who you play.
What about me?
Well, you're Falcon, of course.
Falcon? Again?
I'm tired of being the bad guy.
But you do it so well.
So... is everybody all right
for Saturday?
Fine.
No problem.
Odo?
Uh... what, what do you
want me to do again?
Save the Queen.
Not only that
you get to drive around
in fancy automobiles
and go to posh parties.
Ah...
And steal her away from Falcon.
He steals my girl?
Um...
maybe you'd better get
another Nigel Dunlap.
Are you kidding?
Look at her.
I'm... I'm busy on Saturday.
We'll do it
when you're not busy.
I don't think so.
I'm sorry.
I... never
should have agreed
to be part of this
in the first place.
Sorry.
Well, it looks like
we'll have to find
someone else to play Odo's part.
I'll do it.
I've already told you...
I don't want to play dabo,
I don't want a holosuite
and I don't want
anything to eat.
Can I interest you
in my collection
of Risean tapestries?
Why don't you leave her alone,
Quark?
Can't you see
she's not interested?
How do I know
she's not interested...
unless I ask?
Maybe you should spend
less time
bothering your customers
and more time keeping an eye
on your business?
Don't worry.
I can keep my eyes on more
than one thing at a time.
Really?
What about him?
He's got a graviton emitter
hidden in his ring.
He's manipulating the table
for his friend over there.
- Dabo!
You're very observant.
Thanks.
Are you waiting for someone?
You.
Where have you been all my life?
Pardon me?
Isn't that what you
were hoping I'd say?
No, it's just that you
keep glancing at the door.
I'm waiting for someone.
That's all I meant.
Sorry.
I thought you had other things
on your mind.
Must be those bedroom eyes
of yours.
Bedroom eyes?
You probably get that
all the time.
Not really.
If anyone bothers you again...
let me know.
I'm Security Chief Odo.
My office is
just across the Promenade.
I'll be all right.
Well...
I have to go...
to work...
in my office.
Across the Promenade.
Exactly.
Look at this.
I was checking the contents
of one of those crates.
A tentacle grabbed my hand.
Gagh.
Klingons have been getting
regular shipments of it
since the day
they were posted here.
I can't believe
they eat that stuff.
Hmm.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
What are you looking at?
Well, I'm...
Actually, I'm...
Never mind.
What?
Ah... it's embarrassing.
Would you just tell me?
Well, last night...
a woman in Quark's
told me I have...
bedroom eyes.
I'm trying to see if it's true.
Tell me about this woman.
She thought I was trying
to seduce her.
It was all just
a misunderstanding.
If you say so.
You going to see her again?
I have no idea. Why?
Obviously,
she's very perceptive.
Meaning what?
Meaning...
you should see her again.
Hello again.
What's this all about?
You tried to break
into the station computer.
Why?
My friend never
showed up last night.
I wanted to check
the passenger manifests
to find out if he came aboard.
Why didn't you come to me?
I could've checked
the manifests for you.
When you grow up on Finnea Prime
you learn
not to trust policemen.
Dataport bothering you?
The security protocols
protecting your computer
generated some nasty feedback.
I know.
I designed them that way.
Nice job.
I couldn't stay interfaced
long enough to break
past the encryption lockouts.
That was the idea.
Tell me, Arissa...
what's a nice woman like you
doing with a dataport?
They're not illegal.
They ought to be.
People tend to use them
to access information
other people don't want them
to access.
I've heard that.
This Idanian you were
waiting for in Quark's...
Tauvid Rem...
what were you meeting him about?
A personal matter.
Well, I suppose I could just
go to his quarters and ask him.
I'd rather you didn't.
It's a delicate situation.
I'm listening.
Tauvid's well-known for...
finding people...
people who don't necessarily
want to be found.
He's helping me
locate my daughter.
I gave her up
when she was born 15 years ago.
I see.
He told me he had information
about her.
That's all I know.
I've been looking for her
for a long time.
Please...
let me talk to him.
All right.
I'll take you to him.
We'll sort out the rest later.
Thank you.
Maybe he's not in.
According to the access log,
he's inside.
It's Security.
Hello?
He's not here.
Oh, yes, he is...
what's left of him.
The residue we found
contains Idanian DNA.
I think it's safe to assume
that it came from Tauvid Rem.
Do you have any idea
why someone would want
to kill him?
No, but considering
what he did for a living
he probably had dealings
with all sorts
of marginal characters.
Maybe it was a robbery.
What makes you say that?
I didn't see any personal
belongings in his quarters.
Did your deputies find anything?
No.
Well, whatever happened
I doubt it had anything
to do with me or my daughter.
Now, that depends.
It's possible someone doesn't
want you to find your daughter.
Tauvid didn't give me
any indication of that
when we spoke.
When was that?
About three days ago.
Oh, I can't believe this.
I was so close to finding her
and now I'm going to have
to start all over again.
That's if you'll let me.
If?
In case you'd forgotten
I'm facing charges for trying
to break into your computer.
Considering you weren't
able to access
any secured information...
I've decided
to drop those charges.
I appreciate that very much.
You're free to go.
Thank you.
You're a very kind man.
I hope you find your daughter.
Morn!
We're closed.
Go home.
I'm afraid the Assay Office
is closed for the evening.
If you want to secure
any valuables
you'll have to come back
in the morning.
Thanks.
I'll do that.
I didn't realize
I tripped an alarm.
You didn't.
You're good.
I still got caught.
I've been following you.
I didn't know.
I'm good, too.
So...
did you find anything
in Tauvid's locker?
Would you believe me
if I said no?
Actually, I'd have
you strip searched.
That might be fun.
But in the interest
of saving time...
I've never seen a data crystal
quite like this.
Looks like it has a phase
inverter embedded inside it.
It's not going to be easy
to decode.
Given that all it contains
is information
about a missing girl
Tauvid went to great lengths
to secure it.
You know how Idanians are.
They're a secretive race.
You realize it would
be a simple matter
for me to have you
examined by a doctor
to determine if you've
ever been pregnant.
You keep threatening to have me
stripped down and examined.
I'm trying not to read
too much into that.
You don't have a daughter,
do you?
No.
That's probably the first true
statement I've heard you make.
Not quite.
I meant what I said
about your eyes.
What's on the crystal?
I don't know,
but I need to find out.
Why?
Because if I don't, I'm dead.
Maybe you'd better start
at the beginning.
I work for a man named Draim.
Ah.
I see you've heard of him.
He's with the Orion Syndicate.
If I'm not mistaken
he specializes in blackmail
and extortion.
How do you fit in
with his organization?
I access computer systems
and steal information for him...
government data, business
plans... whatever he asks for.
I hope you're well paid.
It's a very dangerous
line of work.
Trigger the wrong
security protocol
you could end up
with permanent brain damage.
I think about that
from time to time
but there's not much
I can do about it.
You don't quit
the Orion Syndicate
unless they say you can.
Do you want to quit?
That's why I came
to meet Tauvid.
Who was he?
I don't know.
Then why did you
come to meet him?
He told me
he had information...
information I could use
to break away
from Draim free and clear.
What made you believe
that he was telling the truth?
I don't know.
I just did.
I'm not even sure how he knew
I wanted to get out.
Did he tell you
what this information was?
No.
But for some reason,
I decided to trust him.
Oh, I know this sounds insane.
I guess I was desperate.
Did you tell anyone
you were coming here?
No, but Draim must have
monitored my communication.
How else could he have
gotten his people here
before I arrived?
So you think
Draim had Tauvid killed
to stop you
from getting this crystal.
And whoever he hired is
probably still on the station.
You can be sure that Draim
wants to know
what's on that crystal
as much as I do.
What are you smiling about?
Oh, I'm just picturing myself
trying to explain all this
to the authorities
back on Finnea...
not that they'll listen.
They'll just send me to prison.
I'm not turning this over
to the Finneans.
You're not?
I'm placing you
in protective custody
while I have someone
try to access the crystal.
In the meantime, I want you
to look at security recordings
made at the airlocks.
Draim was probably careful
not to send anyone
you'd recognize,
but you never know.
Why are you doing this?
Doing what?
Helping me.
Why not?
You mean, you're just doing this
out of the kindness
of your heart?
I... don't have a heart.
You could have fooled me.
What'd you get?
It's called hasperat.
Where is she?
She's with that changeling
Security Chief.
Spicy.
Mmm.
They have the crystal.
We've got to make sure
she doesn't access it.
She's so pretty.
I was hoping
we wouldn't have to kill her.
You'll get over it.
Nice room.
Don't get too used to it.
You're not staying here.
Odo to Security.
Begin transport.
There.
Now, if anyone was watching
they'll think you're still
in the other quarters.
Hmm. Good trick.
Hope it works.
Interesting furniture.
I use these things
to practice shape-shifting.
These are your quarters?
I thought this would
be the last place
anyone would look for you.
There's a bed in the other room.
I was planning to stay out here,
so I could keep an eye on you...
if that's all right.
I could use the company.
I have two deputies
stationed outside
in the corridor
posing as a maintenance
crew doing repairs.
And where are you
going to sleep?
I don't need a bed.
I regenerate by reverting
to a gelatinous state.
Mmm. Sounds relaxing.
It is actually.
I'm so tired, I wouldn't mind
being in a gelatinous
state myself.
I understand you haven't
been able to identify anyone
from the security recordings.
No.
I haven't had much luck
identifying Tauvid either.
It's not his real name.
He took
three different transports
to get to the station... used
a different identity each time.
I've transmitted
a picture of him
to the Idanian authorities.
I'm not sure we'll get a reply.
As you said before,
they're a very secretive race.
What about the crystal?
Dax and Chief O'Brien
are still trying to get
past the encryption lockouts.
I could try to interface
with it.
No, that's not a good idea.
The first time
they attempted to access it
the feedback
shorted out the computer.
I'd hate to see what that
would do to your dataport.
Oh, I can't believe
what I got myself into...
walking out on Draim to meet
someone I don't even know.
I must have been out of my mind.
You said you were desperate.
Why do you think
I got involved with Draim
in the first place?
I know life on Finnea isn't easy
but you must have had
other options.
Have you ever been there?
No.
It's not like a Federation world
where everything
is handed to you.
You know
how I ended up with this?
I was a net-girl.
I told myself I wasn't selling
my body since there
was no actual contact...
but I was.
I let men
into my mind for money.
Draim was one of them.
That's how we first met.
Before I knew it,
I was working for him.
He paid me more
than I'd ever seen before.
I was so far removed
from the consequences
of what I was doing
it was easy to pretend
that I wasn't hurting anyone.
I'd hear things now and then.
Some businessman Draim had me
investigate would disappear.
I tried to convince myself
it had nothing to do with me
but after a while,
I couldn't pretend anymore.
I wanted out.
I guess I'm finally going
to get my wish.
Only problem is I'll be dead.
Oh, I don't want to cry.
The dead don't cry.
Arissa...
I'm not going to let
anyone harm you.
You have to trust me.
I do trust you.
But you can't
protect me forever.
Sooner or later,
Draim will get to me.
I've got to find out
what's on that crystal.
I don't think you can
count on whatever's
on that crystal
to get you out of this.
If that's true,
I don't have a chance.
Yes, you do.
If you testified against Draim
you could put him in prison
for the rest of his life.
You could get immunity
for any past crimes
you may have committed...
start a new life.
Testify against Draim?
I would never make it
to the witness stand.
I will take personal
responsibility
for your safety.
I don't care how long it takes.
If I have to ask
for a leave of absence, I will.
You'd do that for me?
Why?
I've done things in my life
I'm not proud of, too.
You worked for Draim.
I worked for the Cardassians.
I never had the courage
to walk away.
You did.
I admire that.
Oh... wait a minute.
You're going to have
to give me a minute
to get used to this.
I've never been admired
for anything
other than the way I look.
Most people can't see
past the surface...
especially when what they see
is so beautiful.
I'm... I-I'm sorry.
I merely meant...
Don't apologize.
Well...
I'm going to see
if they've made any progress
decoding the crystal.
Make yourself comfortable.
I'll check in on you later.
I'm not going anywhere.
Let me help you with that.
Extraordinary.
You just jumped out of
an airplane at 20,000 feet
and yet, there's not a hair
on your head out of place.
Odo.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I need to talk to you.
Alone.
Um, driver, stop the car.
Uh, we'll just be a minute.
Uh, isn't that the woman
I was supposed to steal
away from Falcon?
Well, uh, yes, but since
you didn't show up...
You swept her off her feet.
Sort of.
Tell me...
how did you know
she was interested?
It's that kind of program.
What is this all about, Odo?
You didn't come here
to talk to me about women...
Did you?
Ah...
This is about bedroom eyes,
isn't it?
Who told you about her?
Kira?
Nope.
Dax.
Actually, it was Miles.
Oh...
If people are talking,
it's only because they care.
You put on a good front
but anyone who really knows you
can tell that you're lonely.
If you're interested
in this woman
you have to let her know.
Oh, I can't.
Why not?
What if I?
What if she?
Rejects you?
She might... but you
can't go through life
trying to avoid
getting a broken heart.
If you do, it'll break
from loneliness anyway.
So you might as well
take a chance.
If you don't, she'll move on
and you'll never know
what you might have had
and living with that is worse
than having a broken heart.
Believe me.
We're nearly finished, darling.
Car trouble, Mr. Bashir?
Hi, Odo.
I-I should go.
Thank you, Doctor.
Odo...
This isn't fair.
Odo and I were talking.
Didn't anyone ever tell you
you shouldn't stop
for hitchhikers?
- Hello.
I... didn't expect
to find you awake.
I couldn't sleep.
Uh, if the bed
is uncomfortable, I...
The bed is fine.
I guess you have no news for me?
Chief O'Brien
is going to run a quantum scan
on the crystal in the morning.
I'd like to be there.
I might be able to help.
I'll arrange it.
I'm not in your way, am I?
No.
No, not at all.
I, uh...
I usually read
for an hour or two.
What are you reading?
It's a detective novel.
Oh. Have you figured out
who did it yet?
By the third page.
Well...
I should let you
get back to your book.
I...
don't really feel like reading.
Perhaps we could
talk for a while.
What do you want to talk about?
Hmm. Tell me more.
I could swear that
when we first met...
your nose had
a little curve right here.
Hmm.
Oh, I tend to look
a little different every day.
But you always manage
to make these the same.
Well, I pay special
attention to my scowl.
An air of stern suspicion
is very important
in my line of work.
What?
Why are you looking
at me that way?
I'm...
just trying to figure
something out.
Tell me.
Maybe I can help.
You're the first woman
I've ever been...
close with.
I've never been able
to let down my guard.
I was just wondering...
what makes you different.
Wait a minute.
Have you never been
with anyone else before?
Not with a humanoid.
Well, once...
on my homeworld, I...
had an experience
you might consider...
sexual.
But never with a woman before.
Could you tell?
No.
Good.
I don't ever want
to leave this room.
Can we stay here forever?
Oh, I wish we could.
Arissa?
Everything...
is going to work out.
I want to believe that
but I know
what the Orion Syndicate
does to people
who turn against them.
I don't want to spend
the rest of my life
looking over my shoulder.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have brought it up.
Let's just be together.
All right.
Tell me more about
this encounter you had
on your homeworld.
Hmm?
It was with another changeling.
Our bodies...
became...
intermingled...
Mmm. Sounds nice.
Hmm.
Too bad I'm not a changeling.
Oh, we shouldn't
let that stop us.
She spent the night
in his quarters.
He had her
under protective custody.
Come on, Nerys.
He could have put
her somewhere else.
You know how Odo is...
he likes to be thorough.
It was more than that.
Commander...
What makes you say that?
Instinct.
Jadzia.
What?
You asked to be told when the
sensor array became available.
Thank you.
Odo and a woman...
it was bound to happen
sooner or later, right?
I suppose.
You can begin your experiment
at any time.
I'm talking to Kira.
You're not talking.
You're gossiping.
And besides,
Odo is quite capable
of taking care of himself.
Don't shout across the room.
If you want to...
gossip with us
then come down here.
Where's Odo?
He asked me to arrange
a conference
with Starfleet Intelligence
at 0800.
I guess he's running late.
He's never late.
He's never spent the night
with a woman before.
A woman?
That's nice.
Isn't it?
Constable.
Good morning.
Starfleet Intelligence
is ready when you are.
Did you see the look
on Odo's face?
I am telling you,
something happened.
I talked to Draim.
The woman asked to make a deal.
She gives us the crystal,
Draim lets her go.
So we don't have to kill her.
Don't be stupid.
As soon as we get
the crystal, she dies.
Oh.
Makes sense.
You can release the Talarian
as soon as he's sober
but tell him to stay
away from the raktajino.
It obviously doesn't
agree with him.
I'll be in Science Lab 4.
Can I help you?
You're Security Chief Odo?
Yes.
I'm here about the communication
you sent
to the Idanian government.
- Go on.
- Where's Arissa?
Is she safe?
You know her?
Better than she knows herself.
What does that mean?
She's not who she seems to be.
She's an intelligence agent
with my government.
She was sent to infiltrate
Draim's organization.
That's not possible.
She would have told me.
She doesn't know.
I-I don't understand.
We gave her a new identity
before we sent her in.
All her previous memories
were removed and stored
on the data crystal.
If you take me to her,
I'll explain the rest.
Chief, are you all right?
The data crystal...
where is it?
Forget about the crystal...
we've got to find Arissa.
That crystal is Arissa.
She took the crystal.
I don't know where she went.
It generates
a distinctive signal.
We might be able to track it.
Is anyone here?
Just me.
What's wrong?
I've lost it.
The crystal's quantum signature
starts to fade
after a few minutes.
Do you have it?
Maybe.
I thought we had a deal...
your life for the crystal.
I just want to make sure
that you live up to your end.
Your turn.
Do you really think
I'd be stupid enough
to come here with a weapon?
Indulge me.
Very smart.
Do you have any idea
what's on this?
No.
You're going to have
to figure that out for yourself.
Oh, don't go yet.
You haven't met my associate.
How are you?
Fine, thank you.
Draim and I had a deal.
He was in a very emotional state
when he agreed to it.
The truth is...
you really hurt his
feelings when you left.
He liked you.
Maybe you should
close your eyes.
You were supposed
to secure the doors.
I did.
Don't move!
Are you all right?
Yes.
I just wish I knew
what this is all about.
The memory transfer
will take a few minutes.
How long was she undercover?
She volunteered
for the operation two years ago.
After we altered her memories,
we placed her on Finnea.
She woke up the next morning
believing she was
a different person.
With no memory of her former
life as an intelligence agent.
That was crucial to the plan.
Draim employs telepaths
to scan everyone
who works for him.
It was the only way
to get past them.
We left her in place long enough
to become a trusted member
of Draim's organization.
When we were ready to recall
her, we had Tauvid make contact.
We'd imprinted a trace memory
designed to make her feel
she could trust him.
That way, she'd agree to meet.
With what she knows about Draim,
we're going to be able
to cripple
his entire organization.
As soon as she's debriefed
we plan to issue
the indictments.
You make it sound as if it all
went according to plan.
She was nearly killed.
She knew the risks
when she volunteered.
We did everything we could
to minimize them.
Every stage of this operation
was meticulously planned.
Including what just happened
in the cargo bay?
Why didn't you tell us
what was going on
when you found out Tauvid
had been killed?
If Draim's people had
monitored the transmission
it would've compromised
the entire operation.
We couldn't risk it.
All that matters
is that she's safe...
and that Draim is going
to prison for a long time.
The transfer's complete.
I'm going to take her
to surgery.
Yes?
Arissa?
That's...
not even your name, is it?
There's something
you need to know.
I'm married.
I have a husband.
I see.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be.
You didn't know.
It's not your fault.
I fell in love with a woman
who never really existed.
She did exist.
She was real.
And she loved you.
In a way...
she still does.
Will I ever see you again?
I... don't know.
I'll never forget you, Odo.
Never.