( phaser fire
and yelled commands )
Who's winning the war?
It's too early to tell.
It's been three days.
Don't remind me.
They found a nest.
Well, that's good.
It's not the main nest.
That's not so good.
I thought
Chief O'Brien
trapped the last vole
on the station months ago.
Well, obviously,
he missed a couple--
a married couple.
They breed like tribbles.
But they're not as cute.
They're disgusting
hairy little creatures
with ravenous appetites,
and I want them gone.
Oh, Quark.
I know, I know--
this is just
a temporary setback.
The bar will open again,
and I can get back to my life.
I'm glad you
realize that.
The only trouble is,
I hate my life.
( door chimes )
( sighs )
Come in.
Hello, Brother.
What do you want?
You have every right
to be depressed, Brother.
Ever since you were blacklisted
by the Ferengi
Commerce Authority
it's been one thing
after another, but...
I have some news
that's going to cheer you up.
I doubt it.
Trust me on this
one, Brother.
I'm about to make you
very, very happy.
Really?
Really.
Come on in.
What's she doing here?
We're getting married!
Oh... I wish I was dead.
He's been a little
depressed lately.
I don't want to live.
I think you need someone
to talk to...
someone to pamper you.
I think I need to be alone.
You know who
I talk to
when I'm feeling
a little low?
Yeah, me.
Not when it's something
really important.
Let me guess--
Chief O'Brien?
That's not a bad guess.
Rom... just tell me
who it is.
Then you can leave, and I
can go back to my brooding.
There's only one person
in my life
who's always
been there for me
who's never too busy
to listen
who reassures me
when I'm scared
comforts me when I'm sad
and who showers me
with endless love
without ever asking anything
in return.
I'd like to meet
this person.
So would I.
You already know her.
And she'll always be
there for you, Brother
with open arms.
( doorbell buzzes repeatedly)
Quark?
Mother.
Moogie...
( voice breaks ):
hold me.
Of all the Bajoran prophecies
I think my favorite
is Horran's Seventh--
The one that starts:
"He will come to the palace
"carrying a chalice..."
"Bearing no malice..."
"Overflowing
with sweet spring wine."
Someone's been studying
the ancient texts.
It's important
to Leeta.
She wants
a traditional Bajoran wedding.
And you've agreed to it?
Oh, that's
very sweet, Rom.
Is she doing
the same for you?
I mean, learning to
be a Ferengi woman?
Memorizing
the Rules of Acquisition...
Not likely.
No, Leeta's not the type
of woman to quit her job
stop wearing clothes
and never go out
in public again.
That's okay.
I just want her to be happy.
That's a very
enlightened
attitude, Rom.
Rom is not your
traditional Ferengi male.
I... guess not.
You're probably the least
Ferengi-like Ferengi
I've ever met.
I... guess so.
Oh, that's not
a bad thing, Rom.
No traditional
Ferengi male
could ever marry a
non-Ferengi and be happy.
Well, he could
never trust her.
So you see, Moogie, the voles
aren't the real problem.
They're just a symbol
for everything else
that's gone wrong in my life.
You've had a tough
year, Quark.
That's an understatement.
I see all these great
opportunities out there
and I can't do anything
about them.
Without a Ferengi
business license
it's like I don't exist.
I understand why
you felt the need
to escape for a while,
but why come here?
I had no place else to go.
Are you sure
about that?
Oh, now, don't
give me that look.
You and I both know
we've never really
gotten along.
You disapprove
of me, Quark.
You always have.
"Moogie, stop
wearing clothes."
earning profit."
You have stopped,
haven't you?
I mean, earning profit.
Wearing clothes is bad enough,
but profit--
You see what I mean?
I know the two of us
living under the same roof
isn't going to be easy,
but you're my mother...
and I love you.
And I love you, too, Quark.
But when you say
"living together"
what are we talking about--
a day, a week?
Two weeks?
I don't know.
I guess
until I start feeling better--
unless, of course,
you don't want me.
You're my son.
How could I refuse you?
Then you'll remove
all that unnecessary clothing?
Don't push your luck.
Where are you going?
To my room.
I'm exhausted.
What you need is some
of your mother's cooking--
some nice, juicy tube grubs.
I never liked your tube grubs.
I'll pre-chew them for you.
Maybe later.
Hello, room.
Where's all my stuff?
If she's thrown out
my Marauder Mo action figures...
Grand Nagus?
Quark, what are
you doing here?
Uh... I'm visiting my mother.
That's no excuse!
You've been banned
by the FCA.
You must leave
Ferenginar at once!
Got to go.
The Nagus,
he knows I'm here.
Wait a minute.
What's the Nagus doing
in my closet?
The Nagus?
Moogie?
Zekkie!
You might as well come out!
"Zekkie"?
( whispering ):
What's going on?
The next time you visit
I'd really appreciate it
if you called first.
That doesn't answer my question.
"Sometimes the only thing
"more dangerous
than a question
is an answer."
Rule of Acquisition 208.
You're in trouble
again, aren't you?
What have you done now?
Whatever it is, I had
nothing to do with it.
Tell him, Moogie.
Tell him I'm innocent.
Relax, Quark.
I'm not in any trouble.
You're not?
Why would she
be in trouble?
I don't know.
I-I-I just thought,
since you're here...
Uh... I don't...
I don't know what I thought.
I'm so confused.
About what?
It's all really quite simple.
You see, Quark, uh...
your mother and I, uh...
are in love.
How did you
two... meet?
We met at the global
tongo championships.
That's right.
I was playing in the Golden
Masters Division.
And I was tucked away
in the subbasement playing
in the Female Division.
Anyway, word
leaked down to us
that the Grand Nagus
was having
a little difficulty
with his game.
Well, for some reason
my purchases
kept exceeding my sales.
So I wrote him a note
offering some
helpful pointers
on how to firm
up his game.
And they worked.
I made a spectacular comeback
and won the tournament
for the 27th year in a row.
ISHKA:
Zekkie sent me a very nice
"thank you" note.
Before I knew it
we were corresponding
regularly.
Your mother's letters became
the highlight of each day.
It was clear we had to meet.
Imagine his surprise
when he found out
I was a female
and your mother,
no less.
I almost had a stroke
but, uh... I recovered.
And we've been seeing
each other ever since.
( both cooing )
Does anyone know about this?
Of course, no one knows
and you're going
to keep it that way.
My lips are sealed.
They'd better be.
Oh, jellied gree worms.
Maihar'du
you are
too good to me.
Mm, mm, mm, mm.
He treats me like a queen.
That's because
you deserve no less.
Zekkie, they don't come
any sweeter than you.
( laughing )
I don't believe it.
What's that, Quark?
Uh, nothing.
I've never seen you
looking happier.
That's because
I've never felt happier.
( giggling )
Well, my dear
time to get back
to running the Empire.
Try not to miss me
too much.
I miss you already.
That's my girl.
Oh, Lobekins...
don't forget
your appointment calendar.
Thank you, my prize.
Your mother
is a rare jewel, Quark.
Worship her...
as I do.
( blows kiss )
Incredible.
Quark...
if you're going to give me
a hard time about this--
Give you a hard time?
You and the Nagus?
I couldn't be happier...
for all of us.
No sign of
a single vole.
I think we
got them all.
ROM:
Chief
is it all right
if I take
a slightly longer
lunch than usual?
I need Leeta to sign this.
The Waiver of Property
and Profit.
Ferengi females
aren't allowed
to own property
or earn profit.
The WP&amp;P states
that, in the event
the marriage ends
the female gives up
all claim
to her husband's estate.
And you expect Leeta
to agree to this?
I agreed to wear the earring.
So either Leeta signs this
or the wedding's off.
I may not be
a traditional Ferengi
but I'm still a Ferengi.
It's your life
but I think you're making
a big mistake.
I think I'd be making
a bigger mistake if I didn't.
Besides, Leeta loves me.
You'll see, Chief.
She'll sign it.
Are you crazy?
I'm not going
to sign this.
Why not?
Because a marriage is
about sharing everything
including money.
Not on Ferenginar.
We're not on Ferenginar.
But I'm a Ferengi.
And I'm not.
"Females and finances
don't mix."
Rule of Acquisition 94.
That's a stupid rule.
It's true.
You're just like her.
You're after my money.
Like who?
My first wife...
pretending that
you care about me
but, all the time,
it's my profits
that you
really care about.
Rom...
I love you...
not your latinum.
Then prove it.
Sign the WP&amp;P.
Never.
Then the marriage is off.
You bet it is.
My dear, you reek
of tube grubs.
( sniffing )
So do you, Lobekins.
Are your ears
tingling?
Mine, too.
( both laughing )
So tell me, Nagus--
how was your day?
Oh, you know how it is.
Arcybite ore futures
are continuing to increase
and the Bolians
have finally agreed
to allow the Ferengi
Gaming Commission to take over
all their
gambling emporiums.
And... and...
Huh? Mm... Oh!
I have decided to allocate
extra funds for research
on a new breed
of Hupyrian beetles.
Those little fellows
are going to revolutionize
the entire beetle snuff
industry.
Now that's what I call
a busy and productive day.
QUARK:
No wonder
the Ferengi economy
is growing at a record pace.
Costs are down,
profits are up...
And opportunity is
around every corner.
Zekkie, you've done
quite a job.
And your people love you
for it--
your business acumen,
your negotiation skills
your kindness and generosity.
Forget it, Quark.
I'm not going to reverse
the FCA's decision.
They revoked your
business license
and they're the ones who are
going to have to reinstate it.
But you're the most powerful man
on Ferenginar.
You can do whatever you want.
True, but contracts
are the very basis
of our society
and you broke a contract
with another Ferengi.
If I were to intervene
on your behalf
I would be
encouraging others
to violate the law!
And that I will not do!
Moogie...
talk to him.
He makes a very
good point, Quark.
What you did was wrong.
Thanks.
I knew I could count on you.
( slurping )
And I'd watch my tone
of voice if I were you.
Well, my dear, shall
we take a stroll
in your garden?
Oh, and, Quark, will
you do me a favor?
Help Maihar'du
clear the table.
He's not as young
as he used to be.
( sighs heavily )
( whir of active transport )
Brunt, FCA.
What are you doing
in my closet?!
Conducting official
FCA business.
In my closet?
I didn't want the "happy
couple" to see me.
Happy couple?
Oh, don't play innocent
with me.
I know all about their
perverted little love affair.
I had nothing
to do with it.
They met playing tongo.
I only found out
about it today.
She's your mother, Quark
and that makes
you responsible.
And right now,
she's endangering
the very foundation
of Ferengi society.
I can see her now,
whispering in the Nagus' ear
contaminating
his very thoughts
with her twisted
female philosophies.
I tell you, Quark--
if we don't put an end
to their relationship
you're going to see
clothed females
walking down the streets
of Ferenginar
in broad daylight.
If I had my way
I'd climb to the top
of the Tower of Commerce
and denounce your mother
to the crowd below
but... we must
spare the Nagus
even a hint of
public disgrace.
We've got to put an end
to their relationship but...
( whispering ):
privately.
Quietly.
So, what are you
going to do?
I'm not going
to do anything.
You are.
Me?
Who else?
She's your mother,
and the Nagus--
for reasons that
elude me completely--
likes you.
You're in the
perfect position
to poison their
relationship.
Why should I help you?
You revoked
my business license.
I'll give you a new one.
You've got a deal.
Once again, O Nagus,
you have proven
that you have the wisest lobes
in all of Ferenginar.
That's what they pay me for, eh?
( chuckling )
I need to speak to the Nagus.
It's a personal
matter--
nothing for you
to worry about.
What do you want, Quark?
I just dropped by
to pay my respects.
Well, in that case, pay them.
Oh.
Feel better?
Now go.
Before I do
I just want to say
how proud I am
that you consider my home
your home.
My mother is a very lucky woman.
And I am a very lucky man.
I guess the only one
around here
who isn't lucky
is you, Quark.
( snickering )
I just think it's great
that she's found someone
who cares for her so deeply
that he can ignore
all those vicious rumors
about her.
Oh, you mean the rumors
about her earning profit?
I know that whole story.
The FCA made her give up
every strip of latinum
she made.
( sneezing )
I'm talking about
the other rumors.
The ones that say that she
hasn't given it all back.
Oh, nonsense.
Of course, it is,
and the wildest rumor has to be
what she plans to do
with her fortune--
that she's going to fund
a political revolution
to end the male domination
on Ferenginar.
You mean...
equal rights for females?
It's crazy, isn't it?
I mean, so what
if she wears clothing
or that she's managed
to worm her way into the heart
of the most influential
Ferengi alive.
Those aren't crimes, are they?
Absolutely not.
And what if she's as cunning
and ruthless as any male?
That doesn't mean
that she's not to be trusted...
does it?
The important thing is
that she loves you
and that you're not some pawn
in her plans
for world domination.
World domination?
By a female?!
It's a horrifying thought.
Luckily, they're just rumors.
Rumors.
Well, time to go.
I'll see you tonight, Nagus.
I know Moogie can hardly wait.
For what?
For you to get home.
Now that he mentions it
she really has no business
wearing clothes
i-in front of her Nagus.
( Ishka humming )
I should start dinner.
Zekkie'll be here
any minute.
What do you say to
some nice slug steaks?
I'm not hungry.
Quark, the power
cells are empty.
I must have been
too depressed to notice.
It's the FCA
ban, isn't it?
It's awful.
You don't know what it's like
to be denied the opportunity
to earn profit.
Oh, yes, I do.
I know exactly
what it's like.
It's worse for a male.
Is it?
Moogie...
I'm...
in no mood to argue
politics right now.
I'm too distressed.
All right, Quark.
I'll talk to the Nagus.
I'll see if I can
convince him
to intercede
on your behalf.
Oh, Moogie.
You're a manipulative,
self-centered conniver.
Thank you.
Now, Zek'll be
here any minute.
I'll make myself scarce.
Good luck.
I'm counting on you.
ODO:
Commander, I'm sorry if
the Klingons are unhappy
but station rules
are station rules.
I am well aware
of station rules
but General Martok
is a great warrior.
And he has no business
being in a holding cell.
He threw one of his
men off that crossway.
That was
a disciplinary measure.
Oh.
Besides, K'retok
was not injured.
He was barely shaken up.
As opposed to the
Bolian Ambassador.
K'retok only missed
her by a centimeter.
But he did miss her.
Constable...
release General Martok.
Sir...
Mr. Worf, tell the General
that this is not
a Klingon space station.
If he can't abide
by the regulations
I'm sure Chancellor Gowron
will send us someone who can.
Understood.
Constable?
( sobbing )
Do you hear that?
( sobbing continues )
Rom?
Are you all right?
I'm fine Captain.
Thanks for asking.
( continues
sobbing )
The wedding is off.
I'm sorry.
Don't be, Captain.
These are tears of joy.
Carry on.
LEETA:
I hate him.
KIRA:
No, you don't.
All he loves
is latinum.
No, he doesn't.
Canceling that wedding
was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
No, it isn't.
I am so glad
he's out of my life.
No, you're not.
Major... you haven't
been listening to me.
Yes, I have.
It's how I know
you love him.
( Ishka sobbing )
Moogie! I'm home!
So, how'd it go?
Am I reinstated?
( sobbing )
What's wrong?
Did the Nagus say no?
Don't you think about
anyone but yourself?
Of course, I do.
I just think
about myself first.
Now tell me, what's wrong?
He left me.
All I asked him was to
reinstate your license
and the next thing I
know, he's accusing me
of plotting to overthrow
the government.
That's ridiculous.
He said I didn't
really love him
that I was just using him
that I was a scheming,
profit-hungry female
who couldn't keep
her clothes off.
The nerve.
Oh, Quark...
I don't know what I'm
going to do without him.
I don't know what he's
going to do without me.
Moogie, I'm sorry,
but these things happen.
It's probably
better this way.
No, it isn't.
It's a disaster--
for all of us.
( taps panel )
Brunt, FCA.
I hope you've had
a productive day.
I certainly have.
You're smiling, Quark.
Therefore, I assume
your mother is not.
It's hard to smile
when you have a broken heart.
Now, about
my business license...
As of this moment,
it's as valid as my own.
Congratulations, Quark.
You're a Ferengi again.
I always was.
♪ Breakfast. ♪
I'm not hungry.
Moogie, you have
to eat something.
Why?
Because... life goes on.
There are other
slugs in the sea.
You're leaving,
aren't you?
You're going back
to Deep Space 9.
How did you know that?
You spent all morning
jellying gree worms
which tells me that your
conscience is bothering you.
You feel guilty
about leaving me alone.
Well, don't.
I don't need you.
I don't need anyone.
Okay. Then,
I'll go pack.
( humming )
( monitor chiming )
Who could that be?
Hello, Rom.
It's Quark.
Quark-- that's what I said.
I want to see you in the Tower
of Commerce right away.
Don't keep me waiting.
Why is the Nagus
calling you?
I have no idea.
I bet it's about me.
I doubt it.
But then... it could be.
Either way,
I'll do all I can
to straighten things out
between the two of you.
That's a promise.
( sighs )
You want me to be
First Clerk to the Nagus?
That's right, Quark--
my own personal
financial assistant.
What do you say?
Why me?
Consider it a reward
for saving me
from that wretched
mother of yours.
What about my bar?
Do you want to be a bartender
all your life?
I'm offering you
something more--
the chance to participate
in the major decisions
that shape this glorious
financial empire of ours.
Well, when you
put it that way...
Good. Then you can begin
by briefing me
on today's petitioners.
I need your access code.
3-7-4 slash 1-5-5.
It's not working.
You must have
put them in wrong.
3-7-4 slash 1-5-5.
Nope.
Maybe it's 1-5-4.
No, that isn't it either.
But I don't understand.
What did I say
those first numbers were?
3-7-4.
Three, seven, four?
Are those right?
You're confusing me!
I-I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
Oh! It was a six.
What was?
The last number.
Well, isn't that
what I just said?!
A lifetime of numbers--
you can't blame me
for forgetting a few.
( chuckling )
Let's get down to business.
Who's the first petitioner?
Um...
DaiMon Igel.
He wants to know
whether he should sell
his duranium interests
on the open market
or on the Futures Exchange.
An interesting question.
Well, don't just stand there!
Let's see
how duranium's been doing.
Over the last three
trading cycles
there's been an increase
of seven and three-quarters
a decrease of two and an eighth,
and another increase
of 11 and
three-eighths.
Oh. That's a gain of 18 points.
Actually, that's 17.
What are you talking about?!
Seven and three-quarters
minus two
and one-ninth
is seven...
Oh, who cares
about duranium anyway?
DaiMon Igel.
DaiMon Igel? Who's he?
Do I like him?
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Chief.
I need that
phase calibrator
I leant you
the other day.
It's in my tool kit
by the door.
Rom, what are you doing?
These are my profits, Chief--
my entire fortune.
It may be small,
but it's mine.
Why the two piles?
I'm thinking of giving
this pile to Leeta.
That way, maybe she'll
sign the WP&amp;P.
You're offering
her a bribe?
Bribes can be
very effective.
But if she
signs the waiver
then she can't
own anything
so, she'll have to give
it all back to you.
Right.
That's not going
to work, is it?
( sighs )
Rom, I don't think
there's any way
you're going to convince
Leeta to sign that waiver.
Have you ever looked
at latinum?
I mean, really looked at it?
It's so beautiful--
not to mention,
smooth to the touch.
Do you want Leeta
back or not?
"Latinum lasts longer
than lust."
Rule of Acquisition 229.
Maybe, but lust can
be a lot more fun.
Now, answer
the question.
Do you want her
back or not?
I'd give anything
to hold her in my arms again.
Anything?
One jumja stick, please.
What flavor?
Actually...
I don't like jumja sticks.
Then what do you want, Rom?
I want you to marry me.
I'm not signing that waiver.
You don't have to--
not anymore.
I don't have
any profit left to protect.
I don't understand.
I gave all my latinum
to Major Kira for the Bajoran
War Orphans Fund.
She kissed me.
Oh, Rom!
You did that for me?
I did it for us.
Now we have nothing
but our love.
That's all we need.
That...
and my salary
from Quark's.
Well done, Chief--
or should I
call you Cupid?
What can I say?
I'm just
an incurable romantic.
( laughing )
Quark, where have
you been all day?
With the Nagus.
He made me his First Clerk.
I see.
Well, then you've
had a miserable day
haven't you?
The worst day of my life.
How'd you know?
The Market Exchange
is down 199 points.
I don't know
if I should tell you this
but I have to tell someone.
The Nagus, he is...
I know.
His memory isn't
what it used to be.
Did you try
stroking his lobes?
No, I didn't stroke
his lobes.
It helps focus him.
It's also not a bad idea
if you repeat what you say
to him.
Sometimes it takes two,
even three times
before he'll retain it.
You two weren't just lovers.
You were helping him run things.
You're the power
behind the throne?
Well, I wouldn't go that far.
I just helped him a little--
guided him.
A leveraged buyout here
some momentum
investing there....
Why didn't you tell me?
If I'd known what was going on,
I never would have...
Never would have what?
Oh, Quark.
You turned Zek against me,
didn't you?
You filled his head
with all those lies about me.
I didn't know.
Who put you up to this?
Who do you think?
Brunt.
What did he offer you?
Your business license back?
"A Ferengi without profit
is no Ferengi at all."
You taught me that.
The Rules of Acquisition
aren't going to help
you now, Quark.
A 199-point slide.
And that's just
the beginning.
Congratulations, Quark.
You've not only destroyed
my life and Zek's life
you may have triggered
the destruction
of the entire
Ferengi economy.
I hope it was worth it.
My, aren't we early today.
But I suppose
after yesterday's fiasco...
we have no alternative.
A 199-point plummet!
( chuckling )
Haven't seen that steep
a market slide
since Grand Nagus Smeet
and you know
what happened to him?
The only Grand Nagus
to be assassinated
while in office.
What was the name
of his First Clerk?
I believe they buried
them together.
I'm sure we'll
do better today.
No, you won't.
The Market Exchange
will remain closed today.
The FCA Board of Liquidators
has called
an emergency meeting
with the Grand Nagus.
We have some...
questions to ask him.
And by the time
we're through
you'll both be
out of a job.
Why are you
picking on me?
I've done everything
you asked, haven't I?
Everything.
( inhales deeply )
Oh...
Grand Nagus...
Brunt.
Daddy will be so proud.
You knew the truth about the
Nagus all along, didn't you?
You mean,
about Zek's failing memory?
Let me think.
Hmm...
Well, you know,
now that you mention it...
yes, I did.
That's why you wanted
to destroy his relationship
with my mother,
not to protect him...
but to expose him.
I couldn't have done it
without you.
I feel almost... grateful
which is why I'm going
to let you keep
your new business license.
Now, put down those padds,
pack your things
and scurry on back
to that little bar of yours.
ISHKA:
So, how come you're
still here, Quark?
After all, Brunt is right.
You should be back
on Deep Space 9
celebrating your victory.
You've proven yourself
a true Ferengi.
You've betrayed friends
and family
for personal gain.
It sounds so good
when you say it.
But...?
I think I've been hanging around
hu-mans too long.
I think I'm developing a...
Conscience?
It's been coming
for a long time.
I've fought against it,
I really have.
But living with those people
day in and day out
being exposed to their ethics,
their morality...
It's like I've been brainwashed.
You poor boy.
Moogie, I'm serious.
Oh, I know you are
and I know how important
your problems are to you
but frankly, Quark,
right now
I don't give a
damn about them!
We've got much bigger
problems to deal with.
Do you want Brunt
to become Nagus?
Of course not.
he was willing to throw our
entire economy into chaos
just so he could grab power.
Sounds like a true Ferengi
to me.
A Ferengi maybe...
but not a Nagus.
A Nagus has to be
better than that.
His personal greed
has to reflect
the public's greed.
Like Zek.
Exactly.
So what are we going
to do about it?
( laughter )
ZEK:
Did you see their faces?
They thought they had me,
but we showed them.
I answered all their questions,
didn't I?
You certainly did!
The state of the trade
negotiations with the Breen
why I dumped
our lokar bean investments
why I insisted we buy up
every bit of jevonite
we could get our hands on.
You were brilliant!
You know, for
a moment there
I actually thought
that Brunt's head
was going to explode
with frustration!
By the time
I'm finished with him
he'll wish it had!
Blam!
( both laughing )
( all laughing )
He underestimated me.
And he underestimated
you, too.
Me?
I did nothing.
Nonsense.
I might have fooled
those Liquidators
but I'm not fooling myself.
I'm becoming forgetful.
At times,
my memory betrays me.
I hear the Vulcans
have been very successful
at treating memory loss.
Vulcans?
Never liked them.
No appreciation of profit.
But they do make good doctors
don't they?
Make an appointment for me.
I'll never forget
what you did
for me, Rom.
It's Quark.
Ha-ha! Got you!
( cackling )
I may have lost my memory
but not my sense of humor!
( laughs )
As far as I'm concerned,
you're still my First Clerk.
Oh, I'm honored, O shrewd one
but I'm afraid your confidence
in me is misplaced.
Maihar'du?
Quark, I must say
I find your newfound modesty
very annoying.
I need a financial advisor,
and you're it.
If you insist.
But first...
let me introduce to you...
my financial advisor.
Don't tell me.
Zekkie.
Why'd you bring
that female here?
Because the Nagus
deserves to have
the best financial
advisor there is
and that's my Moogie.
All the advice I gave
you today came from her.
I'm not going to lie
to you, Zekkie.
I believe
in equal rights
for females.
( scoffs )
And someday,
I hope you will, too
but I'd never do anything
to hurt you.
But...
what about all those rumors
that Quark told me?
They were lies.
Tell him, Quark.
I guess I stretched
the truth
here and there.
Yah!
Quark, you're fired!
Now the question is:
What am I going to do
with you?
Anything you want.
What man could resist
an offer like that?
( cackling )
Ooh!
Let's go home,
and I'll make dinner.
No! You won't.
Maihar'du
will make dinner.
I've got other
plans for you!
Oh, Zekkie!
( both laughing )
( gasps )
ISHKA:
Quark, dinner's on the table.
I'll be right there.
Leave some room.
For what?
For these.
Oh!
My Marauder Mo
action figures.
I thought you'd
thrown these out.
All these years
I've been keeping them
in storage for you.
I figured you'd want
to take them back
to Deep Space 9 with you.
I sure do.
Do you have any idea
how much these are worth?
Not as much as if you'd kept
them in the original packaging
which is what I told you
at the time.
Even then, you were handing out
sound financial advice.
Thanks, Moogie.
No.
Thank you, Quark.
( whir of active transport )
Brunt, FCA.
But for how much longer?
( chuckles ):
Don't worry about me, Quark.
I'm a survivor.
So, the happy couple
are back together.
If the people only knew.
But they don't
and you're not going
to tell them.
Really?
Why shouldn't I?
Because the Nagus
is ready for you.
If you go against
him, you'll lose
and you know it.
I hate losing.
What Ferengi doesn't?
I may not be able to
destroy the Nagus, but...
you are a different story.
You're going to revoke
my business license?
I don't think the Nagus
will like that.
On the contrary,
I want you
back in business--
gives me an opportunity
to keep my eye on you
because one day you are
going to make a mistake
and on that day,
you're going to lose
more than your license!
But that day is not today.
Now, back in the closet,
where you belong.
It's not over, Quark!
Don't make me come in there
after you.
( whir of active transport )
ISHKA:
Quark, your tube grubs
are getting warm!
Coming, Moogie!
( imitates fighting noises )