Welcome, welcome, welcome.
It's a little
quiet in here.
Oh, you just
beat the rush.
Uh, let me get your order
before, uh...
before I get swamped.
DAX:
I'll have
a Til'amin froth.
I'll have a...
( loud drilling noise )
What was that?
What was what?!
Oh, that!
That's, uh...
( noise stops )
just my nephew
and Chief O'Brien
repairing
some conduit.
You'll get
used to it.
( noise resumes )
The Klingon
restaurant.
It would be quieter.
When are you two going
to be done in there?
When the conduit
is repaired
and brought back up
to safety specs.
Well, hurry up before I
lose all my customers.
I need to get something.
What?
Two root beers.
( noise resumes )
Aah...
Hyperspanner.
Optronic coupler.
How did you know
I was going to ask
for a phase decompiler?
I was paying
attention, sir.
That you were, Cadet.
My father says I can
learn a lot from you.
He says you can
fix anything.
I'm an engineer.
That's what we do.
There.
Good as new.
Amazing.
( yelling, coughing )
O'BRIEN:
Damn!
We repaired
the leak right away,
but the problem was
worse than I thought.
The entire plasma distribution
manifold is shot.
Can you replicate
a new one?
No. Cardassian manifolds
use a beta-matrix compositor
which can't be replicated.
Well, I suppose we could
contact Gul Dukat
and ask him if he has
any spare manifold
systems lying around.
I'm sure he'd jump
at the chance to help us.
Any other ideas?
We could send
a salvage team
to the abandoned
Cardassian station
in the Trivas system.
Empok Nor.
It's the same design
as this station.
The Cardassians pulled out
about a year ago,
but there's good chance that
the plasma manifold system
is still operational.
What about Dominion activity
in the area?
There hasn't been any
for several months.
Strategically, they seem
to have lost interest
in that sector.
But there is
one problem.
It's standard
Cardassian procedure
to booby-trap a facility
before abandoning it,
and a lot of the surprises
they leave behind
are specifically keyed
to attack non-Cardassians.
Sounds like you should
take a Cardassian along.
O'BRIEN:
So, what did Captain Sisko do
to persuade you to come along?
How do you know
I didn't volunteer?
( laughs )
He threatened you,
didn't he?
Nothing so coarse.
The Captain bribed me.
He offered to help me
procure a larger space
for my workshop.
The latest dressmaking equipment
is surprisingly bulky.
Well, whatever he did,
I'm glad you're here.
What's the matter?
Well, it's just that lately
I've noticed everyone
seems to trust me.
It's quite unnerving.
I'm still trying
to get used to it.
Next thing I know, people
are going to be inviting me
to their homes for dinner.
Well, if it makes
you feel any better,
I promise I will
never have you over.
I appreciate that, Chief.
Ah, don't mention it.
Anything to return the favor.
Disarming
Cardassian booby traps
is my least favorite
kind of engineering.
GARAK:
I can certainly
understand that,
but don't worry.
I have some experience
in that area.
Booby traps?
I can't believe
I let you talk me
into volunteering
for this.
Well, it beats
working on the waste
extraction system.
Besides, how often
does an engineer
get to wear a phaser?
Hate to disappoint
you, Pechetti,
but the only thing you're
going to be using that for
is shooting voles.
Empok Nor's been
abandoned so long
they're going to be hungry.
Don't worry.
You play with your wrenches.
We'll watch your backs.
Can I help you, Cadet?
I'm reporting for duty...
sir.
Welcome aboard, Cadet.
Thank you, sir.
And may I say,
it's a privilege
to be here, sir.
You've earned it.
But one more "sir,"
and I'll leave you behind.
Very well, s... Chief.
Let's get going.
Next stop: Empok Nor.
( dice clattering
on board )
GARAK:
What are you doing?
NOG:
Regrouping.
But you're losing.
That's why I need
to protect my assets.
This is not
a financial transaction.
Protecting your assets
is what got you into trouble
in the first place.
You have to go on the offensive.
You have to attack.
Your move.
Oh, this is maddening.
Asking a Ferengi
to play a Cardassian game
is like asking a Klingon to
chew with his mouth closed.
Kotra is not about "regrouping"
or hoarding "assets."
It's about bold strategy
and decisive action.
Chief, would you like
to take on the winner?
I'd love to play kotra against
the hero of Setlik III.
What is that supposed to mean?
Oh, we all know your
distinguished war record--
how you led two dozen men
against the Barrica encampment
and took out an entire
regiment of Cardassians.
If you play kotra
with half that brazenness,
we'd have quite a match.
I'm not a soldier anymore.
I'm an engineer.
I see.
So when you and Dr. Bashir
go into the holosuites
for hours at a time,
you're just repairing them?
What's your point, Garak?
I'm just curious.
Why do you and Dr. Bashir
spend hours in the holosuites,
dressed as fighter pilots,
reliving ancient battles?
We... do it for fun.
It's a game.
And so is kotra.
And I'd love nothing more
than to play
against a man like you.
Maybe some other time.
Chief, here's the
wish list you wanted.
Three categories.
"Must-have"-- which
includes the manifolds
and plasma recoilers.
"Could-use"-- things like,
uh, EPS matrix converters.
And "would-be-nice"--
bypass displacers,
polarity maximizers,
that sort of thing.
Cardassian emblems
and insignias?
Well, a low priority,
but if we happen to find some--
This is a salvage operation,
Pechetti,
not an opportunity to indulge
your collecting obsession.
Right.
Approaching Empok Nor, sir.
Take us
out of warp.
Run a full scan.
I'll take the helm.
NOG:
The station's
main power supply
and life-support systems
are off-line.
No life signs.
I'll take us
into transporter range.
Oh, I don't think we can
risk beaming aboard.
There are probably pattern
scramblers rigged to go off
if they detect
a non-Cardassian
transporter signal.
That could be messy.
We'll have to dock.
Landing pads are sealed.
We'll have to try
an upper pylon.
Won't the airlock
have booby traps?
You can count on it.
And someone
is going to have
to disarm them
before we dock.
I volunteer, sir.
The scanner
in the airlock
might mistake
your enthusiasm
as Cardassian...
but not your DNA.
No, I'm afraid
I'm the only one
who has a chance
of getting through.
( air hissing, thumping )
( thumping footsteps )
( mechanism clicking )
( clattering )
( keypad beeping )
( equipment
powering up )
( static )
( equipment
beeping softly )
( footsteps )
Ah, welcome to Empok Nor.
Thanks for having us.
Take whatever you need.
My house
is your house.
All right, listen up.
We're going to break up
into three teams.
Nog and Stolzoff,
you're with me.
We'll do the "must-haves."
Pechetti and Amaro,
you'll do the "could-use."
Boq'ta and Garak--
"would-be-nice."
Garak has disabled
the central security net,
but there could be
booby traps anywhere.
Don't move into an area
until you've scanned it.
If you see something
that isn't right,
don't touch it.
Call for help.
All right, let's go.
Ugh. What's this?
It's a biogenic
compound.
I wonder
where it came from.
Follow me.
These look
like stasis tubes.
( grunting )
Cardassian.
He's been dead
for about a year.
Hey, look at this.
Interesting.
A regimental badge.
Third Battalion, First Order,
if I'm not mistaken.
This is going
to make Pechetti's day.
Both those tubes have
been activated recently.
Coil spanner.
Flux-coupler.
Uh-oh.
I left it on the runabout.
I'll go get it
right away, sir--
I mean, Chief.
( weary exhalation )
Garak to O'Brien.
Go ahead.
Could you come down
to the Infirmary?
There's something
you should see.
On my way.
That's not right.
( gasps )
A runabout
doesn't disengage
from its docking
clamps and blow up
all on its own.
Which leads me to believe
that the former occupants
of these chambers
are up and about.
If you're telling me
that there are two
Cardassian soldiers
from the Third Battalion
loose on this station,
we're in trouble.
"Death to all."
That was
their motto.
Three simple words,
and they certainly sum up
their credo nicely.
Why would the Cardassians
abandon this station
and leave behind a few soldiers
in stasis tubes?
Why do you think?
To guard it.
The tubes were probably
rigged to wake them up
as soon as someone
came aboard.
Well, that's possible,
but one thing's for sure--
they're out there somewhere
and considering what
they did to the runabout
I don't think
they're too friendly.
Maybe they're just upset
because we haven't
introduced ourselves.
We should find them.
Say hello.
This thing's not working.
Neither is mine.
They must have set up
a dampening field.
We've got to
get out of here.
Let's call for help.
How? The station's
subspace transceiver
was ripped out
when the Cardassians
evacuated.
Well, we could always
try sending smoke signals.
That's not a bad idea.
The deflector grid
is still relatively intact.
If we could modify
the field coils
to emit a series
of covariant pulses--
We could use the station
like an old-fashioned
telegraph
and tap out an S.O.S.
O'BRIEN:
For the pulses to
be strong enough
to reach Deep Space 9
we'll have to boost power
to the induction grid.
Pechetti, you go down
to the Habitat Ring
and bring
the microfusion reactor
back on line.
Stolzoff, you go with him.
Boq'ta, realign
the magnetic flow field
in Conduit G-4.
Amaro will watch your back.
Nog and Garak, you're with me.
We'll set up the
signal generator
in Cargo Bay 4.
NOG:
Aye, Chief.
Use your communicators
as little as possible.
We don't want to give away
our positions.
Any questions?
Let's go.
Well, I'm not convinced
Stolzoff was right
about our Cardassian friends.
Why would anyone
voluntarily
seal themselves
into a stasis tube--
perhaps for years--
just to guard an
abandoned station?
Even the Third Battalion
isn't that fanatical.
Something else
is going on.
O'BRIEN:
Maybe so, but I don't
intend to be here
long enough to find
out what it is.
GARAK: That's the trouble
with humans.
You don't know how to
appreciate a good mystery.
O'BRIEN:
I love a good mystery...
the kind I can
read in bed--
not the kind that's
trying to kill you.
GARAK:
Don't get me
wrong, Chief.
I want to get
off this station
as much as you do,
but I just know
if I don't
figure this out,
it's going to nag
at me for days.
O'BRIEN: All right, now,
let's concentrate
on finishing the
signal modulator
so that we can
get out of here.
You have the whole trip home
to sort out your mystery.
Nog? I need your help
with the phase
discriminator.
On my way, Chief.
( tool whirring )
Do you mind not
aiming that at me?
Don't worry,
the safety's on.
( sighing )
Tell me you did that.
( turbolift whirring )
( turbolift stopping )
( no audio )
( turbolift opens )
Maybe I did activate
the turbolift
without realizing it.
I'm going up.
Okay.
Whoa.
( yelling )
Pechetti!
Stolzoff to O'Brien!
A Cardass--
( grunting )
( scream, thud )
Stolzoff?
Stolzoff!
( sighing )
( glass crunching
underfoot )
BOQ'TA:
The Cardassians
must've surprised them.
They're probably using
the internal sensors
to track us.
Take it easy. We're going
to get out of here,
you can count on that.
But we've got to stay focused.
It looks like
Pechetti was almost done
getting the microfusion reactor
back on line.
I'll finish that
and then I'll go back down
to the cargo bay.
How are you doing
with the conduits?
I-I'm done.
Good.
Now, you and Amaro
get down
to Auxiliary Control
and reconfigure
the pulse generator.
We're going to split up?
We have to.
If we don't
send out a signal,
we're never going
to get off this station.
But, Chief, what if we--
I need you, Boq'ta.
You can do this.
Don't worry.
I'll watch your back.
Stolzoff was supposed to be
watching Pechetti's back.
Look what happened to them.
What if I send
Garak with you, too?
Would that make
you feel better?
I'm flattered. But I'm afraid
I have other plans.
What are you talking about?
I don't intend to stand around
waiting to be killed.
Meaning what?
Meaning I'm going after
those two Cardassian soldiers...
and neutralize them.
Besides, all this whining
is giving me a headache.
AMARO:
You're going to have more
than a headache
if you don't do
what the Chief wants.
Amaro...
You'd like to shoot me,
wouldn't you?
You're dying
to kill a Cardassian--
any Cardassian.
Let him go.
If he thinks he can
neutralize the Cardassians,
let him try.
He'll be doing us all
a favor.
That's the spirit.
Why don't you come
with me, Chief?
Kill a few "Cardies."
It'll be like old times.
Wouldn't you like
to avenge their deaths?
No.
I just want to get
everyone home.
You're fighting your
instincts, I can see it,
but the hero of Setlik III is
still inside there somewhere.
If you're going to go, go.
Nog, you go with Boq'ta
and Amaro.
Aye, sir.
It's all right, Chief.
He can stay with you.
For some reason,
knowing Garak's going
after those Cardassians
makes me feel better.
( terminal beeping )
"Access denied."
Don't you know
how to say anything else?
( sighs ):
Apparently not.
( distant
mechanical thump )
( terminal beeping )
"Access denied."
"Access denied"--
how monotonous.
Looking for me?
( yells )
Oh, that felt...
good.
Chief, why does Garak
keep bringing up Setlik III?
Because he wants
to get under my skin.
But you were a hero,
weren't you?
That doesn't mean
I like thinking about
what happened then.
I was a soldier, Nog.
Sometimes soldiers
have to kill.
GARAK:
Come now, Chief,
don't be so modest.
You did a lot
of killing.
How did you get in here?
Both doors are secure.
"Secure" is
such a relative term,
wouldn't you agree?
I've brought you something.
If you don't mind.
I'm sure Pechetti
would've appreciated it
more, but...
Where did you get this?
From its former owner.
You killed one of the soldiers?
One down, one to go.
By the way, I took a tissue
sample from the soldier's body.
The analysis
was rather fascinating,
in a grim sort of way.
It seems the unfortunate soul
had been given a massive dose
of psychotropic drugs.
Why?
I'm not sure,
but I can tell you one thing--
it wasn't to make him amicable.
The drug's protein structure
seems designed to amplify my
people's xenophobic tendencies.
My guess is that the soldiers
that were left here
were part of a Cardassian
military experiment.
The High Command was probably
looking for a way
to further motivate
their troops.
So they gave them a drug
to make them hate
anybody but Cardassians.
Then why did they attack you?
That's a good question.
Maybe it's an experiment
that went wrong.
That's why they were left
in stasis.
They were
uncontrollable.
I'd love to stay
and hypothesize all afternoon,
but once I've set my mind
to a task,
I hate to leave it unfinished.
What is it, Chief?
You look different.
How so?
That's not the
face of a tailor.
I'm not a tailor.
Not for the moment, anyway.
You know...
I once bought a suit from Garak.
Turns out the sleeve
was a little long.
I remember being angry
when I brought it back
to be fixed.
Is there a point
to this story?
If I'd known
he was so dangerous,
I never would've
complained.
You think he'll get
the other Cardassian?
I hope not. I want
to get him myself.
BOQ'TA:
I don't blame you.
AMARO:
Stolzoff was my friend.
We were
at the Academy together.
She was my sparring partner.
The first time we faced off,
I remember thinking
maybe I ought to
take it easy on her.
She ended up taking
me down so hard,
it knocked
the wind out of me.
( tool buzzing )
That was the last
time I ever pulled
a punch with her.
She had this
one-two combination--
a feint to the right,
a back-handed chop
to the neck--
faked me out every time.
If that spoon-head
gives me the chance,
maybe I'll just
try that out on him.
I think Stolzoff
would've liked that.
( frustrated grunts )
I can't get this loose.
Get me the coil spanner,
would you?
What does it look like?
It's got two pointy things
on the end.
( Boq'ta screams )
( grunting and choking )
( grunt, thud )
( Amaro panting )
He asked me to get
a coil spanner for him.
I just turned my
back for a second.
That's a shame.
And the worst part of it is...
this isn't a coil spanner.
( gasping )
It's a flux-coupler.
That should do it.
O'Brien to Boq'ta.
Boq'ta, come in.
Amaro, what's
going on up there?
( labored gasp )
H-he's out there.
Easy now, easy.
Who's out there?
Garak!
He stabbed me.
( labored breathing )
Chief, why would
Garak do this?
Come on.
He may still be close by.
It doesn't make any sense.
Garak's on our side.
Not anymore.
The psychotropic drug.
He must have been exposed to it.
It's the only explanation.
I should've seen it earlier.
The way he accused Amaro
of wanting to kill him.
The way he insisted on going
after those Cardassians.
He's coming after us,
isn't he?
Yes.
Maybe we can reason
with him.
Get him to try to
understand that the drug
is affecting him.
You saw what he did
to Amaro and the others.
He's not going
to listen to us.
Then we have to finish
setting up the deflector grid.
We've got to get
a distress signal out.
Garak knows what
we're trying to do.
He'll stop us.
Don't we have to try?
Forget it!
I've already lost four crewmen
trying to send out
that bloody signal.
Garak was right.
We should have gone
after those Cardassians
as soon as they attacked us.
You don't wait
for the enemy to come to you.
You go to him.
Come on.
We're going after Garak.
Y-you mean, to kill him?
If that's what it takes
to stop him, yes.
GARAK ( sing-songy ):
I know you're hiding
somewhere...
Ah. There you are.
Garak to Chief O'Brien.
You'll never guess
what I just found.
A kotra board.
The Station Commander
left one in his office.
The pieces
were scattered all over,
but I found the last one
hiding under his desk.
I can't help thinking
what a perfect metaphor
this game is
for our present situation, hmm?
Two players, two minds,
two strategies,
each trying
to outmaneuver the other--
testing the enemy's defenses,
advancing, retreating.
O'BRIEN: We split up.
Enter Ops through
the main corridor.
I'll go through
the Captain's office.
Wait for my signal.
...that, in the game
we're playing
the stakes are life and death,
which makes it
so much more interesting.
( laughing ):
I haven't had
this much fun in years.
My heart's pounding.
The blood's racing
through my veins.
I feel so alive...
and I'd wager, so do you.
( grunts quietly )
( static from monitors )
( rapid breathing )
( grunting )
( yelling )
It looks like I've captured
your last piece, Chief.
If you want it back,
you're going to have
to take it from me.
GARAK:
It's your move, Chief.
What are you going to do?
Attack? Retreat? Surrender?
Listen to me, Garak,
it's the drug.
It's affecting you.
You've got to fight it.
Fight it?
( laughs )
But I'm enjoying myself.
This is the most exciting
game I've played in years.
O'BRIEN:
It's not a game!
Oh, but it is,
and the best thing about it
is that it brings out
the player's true nature.
Where are you, Garak?!
I saw the look in your eyes
when I took the Ferengi
away from you.
You wanted to kill me.
You wanted to strangle me
with your bare hands.
I just want my crewman back,
that's all.
You're a killer, admit it.
We both are.
Behind your Federation mask
of decency and benevolence,
you're a predator,
just like me.
No, I'm nothing like you.
Oh, but you are.
You proved that on Setlik III.
How many Cardassians
did you kill?
Ten? 20? 100?
I don't remember.
Oh, but you remember
how you felt.
The Cardassians
were killing your men.
You had to stop them.
You had to make them pay.
Blood for blood!
You enjoyed killing them,
didn't you, huh?
You enjoyed watching the life
drain out of their eyes.
All right, Garak,
you want to finish this game?
Fine, let's finish it.
You and me, face to face.
Nothing would give me
greater pleasure.
We'll meet on the Promenade.
No weapons!
No weapons.
You have no idea how hard it is
to keep from pulling
this trigger,
but I need you alive.
GARAK:
They've come to cheer
you on, Chief--
your loyal team.
Apparently, they've
forgiven you
for getting
them all killed.
My supporters
may be fewer in number
but they're no less loyal.
I thought we agreed,
no weapons.
What's that in your hand?
Well, how did this get here?
Put yours down.
You first.
Put it down...
or say good-bye to the Ferengi.
Don't do it, Chief.
Oh, he has nothing
to worry about.
I'm not going to shoot
an unarmed man.
What fun would that be?
You wouldn't happen to have
another one, would you?
Naughty, naughty.
Your turn.
I admit I am tempted
to end this right now.
But that would be depriving
myself of too much enjoyment.
( grunting )
I'm disappointed, Chief.
I expected to see the bloodlust
in your eyes
but all I see is fear.
( groans loudly )
Maybe it's true.
Maybe you're not
a soldier anymore.
You're right.
I'm an engineer.
( combadge beeps )
( electronic buzzing )
( grunting )
You okay, Nog?
I'm all right, sir.
Is he dead?
Did you kill him?
No...
I didn't.
He should be all right
in a few days.
I've neutralized
the psychotropic compound
that was affecting
his nervous system.
He looks so peaceful.
It's hard to believe
he's the same man
who attacked us.
In a way, he's not.
The drug brought out
the worst parts of him
and allowed them
to take over.
He wasn't in control
of his actions.
Can I talk to him?
For a minute.
I thought you might like to know
that we salvaged
the plasma manifold.
It's being installed right now.
Mission accomplished.
I guess it didn't exactly go
the way any of us expected.
You know there's going
to be an inquest.
Yes. I've been told that.
Chief, I was hoping
to ask a favor.
Don't worry,
once they know the facts--
It's not about that.
I'd like you
to express my...
deepest regrets
to Amaro's wife.
I'd talk to her myself
but I'm not sure
she'd welcome that.
I'll tell her.
I'd appreciate it.
Julian tells me the blast
broke a couple of your ribs.
Well, it could have been worse.
If I'd been any closer
to that phaser
it would have killed me.
Don't take this
the wrong way,
but... that was the plan.
I understand.
See you around.