ROM: What do you think?
LEETA: I don't know.
What do you think?
I like it.
Don't you?
Rom, it's two handkerchiefs
and a loincloth.
I suppose we could lose the handkerchiefs.
Ferengi tradition or no Ferengi tradition,
I am not going to be naked at my wedding.
Who said anything about naked?
You'll still have the loincloth.
Please show us something else.
There is nothing else.
I've shown you 153
different wedding dresses,
from Tellarite modern
to Risian traditional,
and you've hated them all.
Well, I like number 38.
Number 38?
It had more layers
than a Baduviam tapestry.
-It was elegant.
-It was bulky.
I liked 64.
-Sixty-four?
-( exclaims in disgust )
Well, at least they agree on something.
Why don't you just let Garak
design a dress on his own?
You know whatever he comes up with
will be beautiful.
My dear, I find your blind adoration
both flattering and disturbing.
But she does have a point.
QUARK: Leeta!
That 15-minute break you asked for
was up an hour ago.
Brother, what do you think of this dress?
I don't want to think about it.
All I know is that any marriage
where the female is allowed to speak
and wear clothing is doomed to failure.
Your dabo table awaits.
( exclaims angrily )
There he is.
Let's talk to him.
Now?
Now, Rom.
Keiko and the kids
will be a lot safer on Earth
than they are here.
They've only been gone two days,
and I miss them already.
Still, don't you feel better
knowing they're out of harm's way?
I wish I could convince Jake
to visit Earth for a while.
Captain. Can we speak to you for a moment?
If you're not too busy.
Oh. Go ahead.
Would you marry me?
I mean us.
I mean, would you perform
our wedding ceremony?
It would be a great honor
to be married by the Emissary.
It's not for another two weeks,
so you have plenty of time to get ready.
I guess I'll have to start
brushing up on my Bajoran.
Me, too.
-Captain?
-If you'll excuse me?
Maybe they're not coming.
That would be a nice surprise.
One thing I'll say for the Dominion...
they're punctual.
That's the fifth convoy
headed for Cardassia
in the last five weeks.
I can only imagine how many Jem'Hadar
soldiers are stationed there now.
Too many.
I wish they'd just attack
and get it over with.
I have the feeling you're
going to get your wish.
Thanks for the invite, Dad.
-I haven't had a home-cooked meal since--
-Since the last time you were here.
Sounds about right.
So, uh, what's for dinner?
Ah. Can I get some salsa with that?
Read the headline.
"Bajorans Continue Negotiations
with Dominion."
Go on.
"Station Commander
Opposes Nonaggression Pact."
And the byline.
"By Jake Sisko."
You should have warned me.
I was waiting for the right moment.
The right moment was before
you published the article.
I know. I'm sorry.
But aren't you glad I got a job?
You mean, this isn't a one-time thing?
Nope. I'm now an official correspondent
for the Starfleet News Service.
Well, what about your novel?
I'm not giving up on it,
but, this way,
I get to see my work in print.
And, apparently, I get to see
everything I say in print, too.
( scoffs ) You're a public figure, Dad.
You're the Captain
of the most important space station
in the entire Federation.
You're news.
Don't remind me.
I guess I can't stop you
from doing your job.
Can I quote you on that?
( clears throat softly ) I guess not.
Yamok sauce.
Who would bother to smuggle in
10,000 wrappages
of Cardassian yamok sauce?
Oh. Quark.
That little worm.
He thinks the Cardassians
are going to retake the station.
He's a Ferengi.
You can't blame him for hedging his bets.
But it is a lot of yamok sauce.
What is a yamok, anyway?
What would you like me to do with it?
Major?
I don't care. You decide.
Dump it.
Very good.
Would you mind telling me what's going on?
-What do you mean?
-You and Odo.
You've been avoiding each other for weeks.
-Oh, it's a long story.
-Those are the best kind.
( sighing ) Odo has... feelings for me.
-What kind of feelings?
-The kind that aren't easy to talk about.
Since when?
Since, I don't know-- years.
I just found out about it last month.
That explains a lot.
-It does?
-Not really.
It just seemed
like the right thing to say.
-I had no idea.
-Neither did I.
60 degrees Celsius--
just the way you like it.
Uh, sir...
is it true what they're saying
about the Romulans?
What do they say?
Well, there were some Orion Free Traders
in Quark's last night,
and they heard from a Vulcan diplomat
that the Romulans
signed a nonaggression pact
with the Dominion.
A lot of rumors float around
at a time like this, Cadet.
Just don't forget
the 190th Rule of Acquisition.
"Hear all, trust nothing."
Good advice, sir.
The Romulans.
Sisko to Dax.
Dax here.
Put me through to Starfleet Intelligence.
The Romulans!
I always knew they were without honor!
Now they have proven it.
When did they sign the treaty?
Yesterday. They must
be desperate to side with the Dominion.
Technically,
they're not siding with anyone.
It's a nonaggression pact.
Which means if the Dominion attacks,
they just sit by and do nothing.
The Romulans,
the Miradorn, the Tholians...
the Dominion is making impressive inroads
in the Alpha Quadrant.
And the Bajorans are
still talking to them?
My people will never sign that treaty
or any other agreement with the Dominion.
Meanwhile, more Jem'Hadar ships
come through the wormhole every week.
It must stop.
It's going to stop.
I've talked to Starfleet Command.
They've agreed that no more Dominion ships
can be allowed into the Alpha Quadrant.
How do we keep them out?
We're going to mine
the entrance to the wormhole.
Prevent the Dominion from bringing
any more reinforcements to Cardassia.
If we try to stop those convoys,
it may very well start a war.
Maybe so...
but one thing is certain.
We're losing the peace,
which means a war could be our only hope.
What about pulse mines?
We could equip them
with variable geometry detonators.
( sighs ) Not good enough.
Dominion ships can wait
at the mouth of the wormhole
and pick them off one by one.
What if we cloaked them?
Cloaking doesn't always work
against the Dominion.
Maybe cloaked ships don't,
but I'm thinking much smaller...
each mine no more than a meter across.
Well, mines that small
don't have a lot of power.
It would take dozens of them
to disable a warship.
We'd run out of mines
before they ran out of ships.
Rom! Are you here?
"Cloak. Small. Dozens."
I heard every word.
Well, something's wrong.
You haven't touched your food.
It's my stomach.
Ever since Captain Sisko agreed
to officiate at our wedding,
I haven't had much of an appetite.
I thought you wanted
Captain Sisko to marry you.
I did, but now that he said yes,
it's become so...
real.
I'm going to get married!
Not for another two weeks,
and in the meantime, we have work to do.
But what if Leeta turns out
to be just like Nog's mother?
What if I can't make her happy?
What if this is
the biggest mistake of my life?
-What if--
-Rom!
Self-replication.
That's the only answer.
Self-replication?
If the mines are going to be small,
we'll need a lot of them,
and we'll need a way
to replace them quickly
if the Jem'Hadar try to blast
their way through, and...
Uh-oh. I forgot to request new quarters.
Mine are too small.
Where are Leeta and I going to live?
Rom, I think you're on to something.
I know I am.
I've measured them three times.
There's nowhere to put her prayer mandala.
We could equip each mine
with a replicator unit.
No matter how many
the Jem'Hadar destroyed,
there'd always be more.
We'd program them to swarm detonate...
20 or 30 mines to each ship.
The only problem is you'll have to wait
until the entire mine field
is deployed before you activate it.
Otherwise, the proximity sensors
could cause premature detonation.
Where's Leeta going to put
all her clothes?
I don't have enough closet space.
-I better go talk to Sisko.
-I'll go draw up some specs.
I've got to go to waste extraction.
What did Starfleet Command say?
How many reinforcements
will they be sending?
KIRA: And how soon will they get here?
We're not getting any reinforcements.
We'll have to make do with what we've got.
What we've got isn't enough.
Sir, as Strategic Operations Officer,
I cannot guarantee
the safety of this station
if the Dominion fleet attacks.
Your concerns are noted, Commander.
What's Starfleet thinking?
They must have given you a reason
for denying your request.
-They did.
-And?
I'm not at liberty to discuss it.
Let's just say
Starfleet's resources
will be needed elsewhere.
What could be more important
than defending this station?
That is not for us to decide.
What are our orders, Captain?
Deploy the minefield and prepare
for a Dominion attack.
And when the attack comes?
Then we are to defend the station
until the mines are in position
and the field has been activated.
The Defiant will be unable
to raise shields or cloak
while deploying the mines.
She will be an easy target.
Then it's up to DS9 to defend her.
If the Dominion wants to stop the Defiant,
they'll have to come through us.
You wanted to see me, Constable?
Major, I'd like your permission
to terminate all outgoing
subspace communications.
You really think that's necessary?
This is no time for security leaks.
I've prepared a number of false messages
we can transmit at random intervals
so there won't be any noticeable drop
in our outgoing subspace traffic.
I'll see what I can do.
I'd appreciate that.
Major...
( sighs )
There's something you ought to know.
What's that?
I've been thinking about
asking you out to dinner.
I've been expecting something like this.
I could tell.
You've looked a little uncomfortable
around me lately.
Well, you've looked
a little uncomfortable yourself.
Which is why I wanted you to know
I'm not going to do it.
No dinner invitations, no flowers,
no attempts at changing the nature
of our relationship.
Until the current crisis has passed,
we both need our minds to be clear,
to be free of any
unnecessary distractions.
Well, that's probably a good idea.
So for now,
all we need to concern ourselves with
is deploying the minefield,
maintaining station security,
and preparing ourselves
for a possible invasion.
Hmm...
Well, I don't know about you...
but I feel more comfortable already.
( sighs )
( chuckles )
SISKO: Captain's Log, Stardate 50975.2.
The next Jem'Hadar convoy
is due in five days,
but our efforts to mine the wormhole
have already provoked
a response from the Dominion,
who have sent
their Vorta ambassador, Weyoun,
to speak with me.
What can I do for you, Weyoun?
Captain Sisko...
I'll make this brief.
We know all about the mine field.
I assumed you'd find out sooner or later.
As I see it, you have two choices.
Either you remove the mines,
or we will take this station from you
and remove them ourselves.
I appreciate your directness.
Now, let me be direct with you.
The mines stay.
I will not allow any more
Dominion reinforcements
through the wormhole.
-You will not allow?
-You heard me.
I can see how that might be
your first reaction.
But you and I are reasonable men.
And surely, reasonable men can come
to some sort of
mutually acceptable compromise.
I didn't think the Dominion
believed in compromise.
( sighs )
It saddens me to see how deeply
you misunderstand us.
All the Dominion wants
is to peacefully coexist
with its neighbors.
Then why the continued military buildup?
Why the weekly convoys of ships and troops
from the Gamma Quadrant?
It's the Cardassians.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm pleased to call them allies,
but as you know, they've just been through
a terrible war with the Klingons.
I'm afraid it's left them
somewhat jittery,
so they're understandably
concerned about ensuring
the sovereignty of their borders.
And since they're now
members of the Dominion,
their concerns have become our concerns.
I would think by now
you have more than enough ships
to defend Cardassia.
You may think that, and I may think that,
but the Cardassians--
Oh, yes, I know. They're jittery.
You see our dilemma.
I'm beginning to.
What if...
we agreed to limit our
convoys to cargo ships,
construction units, civilian aid?
Things that will help them get
their economy back on its feet.
Did you know when we arrived
children were starving on Cardassia Prime?
It was heartbreaking.
I had no idea things were so bad.
The Cardassians are a very proud people.
They don't want to admit to outsiders
how dire the situation really is.
So...
are we agreed?
You remove the mines,
and we restrict our convoys
to medical and economic assistance.
That sounds reasonable.
I'd have to discuss it
with Starfleet first, of course.
I'm sure they'll do whatever
Benjamin Sisko recommends.
For my part,
I'll personally speak to the Founders
to secure our end of the bargain.
What about Gul Dukat?
Ah, he'll be furious...
at first.
But we've developed
a fine working relationship,
and I'm sure I can help him
to see the wisdom of our decision.
I will leave it in your capable hands.
You won't be disappointed.
This is a momentous day.
You and I have just taken the first step
towards insuring peace
between our peoples.
They're going to attack.
-Are you sure?
-I am positive.
The moment I mentioned
that we weren't going to remove the mines,
we both knew there'd be war.
Everything else was just words...
a feeble attempt to lull the other side
into a false sense of security.
I didn't buy it,
and I'm sure Weyoun didn't either.
How soon?
As soon as they can get
their fleet from Cardassia.
I'd say as early as tomorrow.
Which means we have to finish
the minefield today.
We need more time.
You don't have it.
We'll do the best we can. Dax out.
General, take your ship
and patrol the border.
At the first sight
of the Dominion ships...
I will sound the alarm.
Don't engage the enemy.
Get back to the station
as soon as you can.
We're going to need you here.
Captain, fighting them at the border
or fighting them here at the station
makes no difference to me.
You don't think
Starfleet could be persuaded
to send us a few more ships, say 50?
I'm afraid not, Doctor. We're on our own.
In that case, I'd better go
and get the infirmary ready.
Mr. Worf, see to the weapons array
and issue combat assignments.
Aye, sir.
Major.
I'll contact the Bajoran Militia,
see if they can spare a few ships.
Forget the Militia.
I need you to contact
the Council of Ministers.
Tell them I need to meet
with them immediately.
As a Starfleet Captain
or as the Emissary of the Prophets?
Both.
That'll get their attention.
Remember the nonaggression pact
the Dominion offered Bajor
a few weeks ago?
Yeah, they're still debating it
in the Council of Ministers.
It'll never pass.
It'll pass if the Emissary endorses it.
You want Bajor to sign a treaty
with the Dominion?
Why?
Major, when I came here,
my orders were to protect Bajor
and help your people
rebuild from the Occupation.
We've succeeded.
And I refuse to see everything
we've accomplished torn down again.
The sad truth is, Major,
if there is a war now,
the Federation can't guarantee
the safety of Bajor,
which means Bajor must
be kept out of the fighting.
I don't like this
any more than you do, Major,
but it's Bajor's only chance for survival.
SISKO: Captain's Log, supplemental.
Bajor has signed the nonaggression pact
with the Dominion.
All Bajoran personnel have been ordered
to evacuate the station.
As someone once said,
"These are the times
that try men's souls."
ZIYAL: Are you sure you
won't come with me?
GARAK: I don't think I'd be
very welcome on Bajor.
I'm not going to be
very popular there, either.
My dear, you're half-Bajoran.
So at least half of you
is going to be accepted.
I'm sure that Major Kira's friends
will take good care of you.
Well, what's going to happen to you?
Oh, well, let me tell you a story.
I once knew a Cardassian,
a dashing, handsome young man
with a promising career.
But one day, through no fault of his own,
he found himself exiled and alone
with nowhere to turn.
But did he give up?
No.
He struck upon a brilliant plan.
Instead of fleeing
for the rest of his life,
he sought shelter
in the one place no one
expected him to go...
in a stronghold of his
people's most hated enemies.
There, surrounded by hostile strangers,
he built a life.
And there, against all odds,
against the merciless logic
of the universe itself,
he thrived.
By becoming the greatest tailor
in the galaxy.
And the moral of the story, my dear,
is to never underestimate
my gift for survival.
( speaking native language )
You may kiss the bride.
Congratulations, Father.
Uh... Moogie.
Thank you, Nog.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I have business to attend to.
Well, that was the most pathetic excuse
for a wedding ceremony I've ever seen.
No bridal auction, no latinum dances,
and the bride...
the bride was severely overdressed.
Nevertheless, you're very happy for us,
aren't you, Brother?
Overjoyed.
( sighs )
I give it two months.
Oh, Rom.
No time for that.
Nog, are Leeta's bags packed?
They're already on the shuttle.
-You mean we're leaving?
-No.
You're leaving.
First Minister Shakaar was very clear.
All Bajorans must leave the station
for their own safety.
But what about you?
My job is here, with Chief O'Brien.
Then I'm not going either.
You see that, Nog?
We've barely finished saying our vows,
and we're already having our first fight.
We're really married.
You've got to go, Leeta.
The problems of two newlyweds
are but a small thread
in the tapestry of galactic events.
You might not understand that today,
or even tomorrow,
but someday you will.
So get on that shuttle
and don't look back.
Nog, take your Moogie to the Docking Ring.
Nice speech, Dad.
I thought so.
Computer, what's the status
of program Sisko-1-9-7?
COMPUTER: All necessary modifications
have been completed.
Program Sisko-1-9-7
ready for implementation
on your command.
NOG: Ops to Captain Sisko.
Sir, we're receiving a message
from the Cardassian border.
It's General Martok.
On screen.
Aye, sir.
MARTOK: Captain, we just detected
a large force of Dominion ships
headed your way.
They should be there within the hou--
Someone is jamming his transmission.
Contact established.
DUKAT: Captain Sisko,
I don't suppose
you would like to surrender
and avoid unnecessary bloodshed.
Absolutely not.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Battle stations.
( alarm blaring )
How much longer?
The Dominion fleet
should be in weapons range in 20 minutes.
Are all the Bajorans off the station?
NOG: The last transport just left.
( sighs ) Let's hope the Dominion honors
the nonaggression pact.
Cadet, put me through to the Defiant.
Yes, sir.
On screen.
Benjamin, I know what you're going to say,
but we've got at least
another hour of work
before we can activate the minefield.
You don't have an hour, old man.
The Dominion is going to be here
in less than 20 minutes.
You're going to be a sitting duck.
Then I hope you can buy us some more time.
Dax out.
Dax to O'Brien.
I know, I know. Work faster.
JAKE: A medical tricorder, hypospray,
dermal regenerator,
and battlefield trauma kit.
Medical tricorder, hypospray
dermal regenerator,
and battlefield trauma kit.
( sighs ) That's everyone.
Now what?
Now we wait...
until the casualties start coming in.
Are you sure you're all right?
I'll be fine.
Besides, my father
won't let me stay in Ops,
and, uh,
I promised the Federation News Service
a firsthand account of the battle.
You'll get it.
Just remember,
Bashir is spelled with an "I."
I must say, Constable,
I admire your composure.
You're an island of tranquility
in a sea of chaos.
What I am is useless.
My entire staff
has been evacuated to Bajor.
I'm not feeling too terribly
useful myself at this moment.
But if it'd make you feel any better,
you could always deputize me.
( scoffs )
I'm sure if the Jem'Hadar
board the station,
you'll make yourself useful.
It's ironic.
When the Klingons attacked the station,
Gul Dukat and I
were fighting side by side.
At one point, he turned his back to me,
and I must admit that for a moment,
he made a very tempting target.
You'd shoot a man in the back?
Well, it's the safest way, isn't it?
But then I thought,
"Well, no, I can't fight
all these Klingons by myself,"
so I let him live.
And now you regret it.
Ah, my dear Constable,
before this day is over,
everyone on this station
is going to regret it.
( device whirring )
Rom...
I've always said you were an idiot,
but I never believed it
more than I do at this moment.
Brother, if you want to insult me,
it's going to have to wait till later.
I'm busy.
Busy doing what?
Preparing perimeter defenses
for the attack.
There are dozens of engineers
that could be doing that.
Starfleet engineers.
Hu-mans.
( device turns off )
You should be on Bajor with your new wife.
That's what Leeta said.
Well, she's right. This is not your fight.
It's not your fight either,
but I don't see you leaving.
I have to look out for my bar.
And I have to look out for you.
-Me?
-You're my brother.
Whatever happens, we belong together.
( device starts up )
Well, like I said, you're an idiot.
NOG: On screen, Captain.
General Martok, take a defensive
position near the Defiant.
They have to finish deploying those mines
no matter the cost.
And they will.
You have my word on it, Captain.
Mr. Worf, activate the weapons array.
Aye, sir.
Captain, as a Major
in the Bajoran Militia,
I must officially protest
Starfleet's refusal
to turn over this station
to my government.
-Your protest is duly noted.
-Good.
Now that that's over with...
Kira Nerys reporting for duty.
Weapons range in one minute.
I've been waiting for this moment
for five years.
First, we reclaim Terok Nor,
then... on to Bajor.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
Or must I remind you
the Dominion just signed
a nonaggression pact with Bajor?
The Dominion might have.
I never did.
The Dominion will honor its treaty,
and as a member of the Dominion,
you will honor it as well.
Where the Dominion leads, I will follow.
I never doubted it.
Attack wings one through five,
head for the Defiant.
Remaining ships, target the station.
We're within weapons range.
Well...
then by all means...
Fire.
Mr. Worf, all weapons fire at will.
Enemy ships are closing on the Defiant.
-Mr. Worf.
-Got them.
-( console beeping )
-Sir, the station's shields are holding.
Impossible.
Federation shields have always proven
useless against our weapons.
I've found it wise to never underestimate
the Federation's technical skill
or Captain Sisko's resourcefulness.
Damar, bring us around for another pass.
Chief, how much longer?
O'BRIEN: Just another couple of minutes.
Take us to our final set of coordinates.
Helm, set course--
Chief, I'm going to have to take
evasive maneuvers.
If you do, you risk setting off
every mine on this ship.
( yells )
And if I don't,
we may not have a ship left!
You may continue your work, Commander.
I will handle the Jem'Hadar.
Who says there's never a Klingon around
when you need one?
( chuckling )
Shields at 35%.
They're preparing for another attack.
Mr. Worf, make every shot count.
Attack wings and batteries,
concentrate your firepower on Section 17
of the Outer Docking Ring.
We have to penetrate their shields.
We've lost main power to the shields.
Switching to auxiliary power,
but I do not know how long it will hold.
( yelling )
-( beep )
-DAX: Defiant to Captain Sisko.
Dax, go ahead.
We've set the last mine.
Activate the field and return
to the station.
Yes, sir. Dax out.
-Sir, the minefields--
-I have eyes, Damar.
This isn't turning out
quite the way I had planned.
It's a minor setback, Weyoun.
Once we take the station,
we'll be able to dismantle the minefield
without interference.
Let's both hope your
confidence is justified.
Damar, signal the reserves
to prepare for a final assault.
The Dominion fleet is regrouping.
( console beeping )
And I'm detecting another wave
of enemy ships entering Bajoran space.
What are your orders, Captain?
We've done all we can here.
Notify all remaining Starfleet personnel.
We're evacuating the station.
MAN: Report to the staging area.
DAX: Worf!
Jadzia.
You should be on the Defiant.
I heard you're not coming with us,
that you've been assigned
to Martok's ship.
It may be some time
before we see each other again.
Worf, we may never see each other again.
This is war.
We must put aside our personal feelings
and focus on the task at hand.
I've been through my share of wars.
I know what I have to do.
But before you leave,
I want you to know
that the answer is "yes."
Yes... Yes to what?
Yes, I will marry you.
That's what you've wanted
from the beginning, isn't it?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Then when all of this is over,
we'll get married.
And if that doesn't
give you a reason to survive,
I don't know what will.
When I first took command of this post,
all I wanted was to be somewhere else...
anywhere but here.
But now, five years later,
this has become my home,
and you have become my family.
And leaving this station... leaving you...
is one of the hardest things
I've ever had to do.
But this war isn't over yet.
I want you to know that while we were
keeping the Dominion occupied,
a Starfleet-Klingon task force
crossed the border into Cardassia
and destroyed the Dominion
shipyards on Torros III.
Your sacrifices...
our sacrifices made that victory possible.
But no victory can make
this moment any easier for me.
And I promise, I will not rest
until I stand with you again...
here...
in this place where I belong.
Sisko to Defiant.
O'BRIEN: Standing by, sir.
-One to beam aboard.
-Aye, Captain.
-Are we ready?
-As soon as you give the word, sir.
Mr. Garak?
I'd like to come along, if you don't mind.
You never know when you
might need a good tailor.
And the simple fact is,
I have nowhere else to go.
Welcome aboard.
-( beeping )
-Dax to Sisko.
The Dominion fleet
is coming around for another attack.
Release docking clamps.
Prepare for departure.
( console beeping )
The Defiant's away.
Contact the Dominion fleet.
Tell them...
the Bajoran government
welcomes them to Deep Space 9.
-( console beeps )
-Message acknowledged.
Good.
It's the last message this station
will be sending out for a while.
Computer...
initiate program Sisko-1-9-7.
COMPUTER: Program initiated.
Dukat wanted the station back.
He can have it.
I don't want to see a drop of root beer
left in this place.
Break out the kanar.
And find me some yamok sauce.
Rom...
assistant manager
for policy and clientele.
Reporting for work, Brother.
What, did you think you could
just walk back in here
and get your old job back?
Actually, I'm a spy...
working for Starfleet.
But don't tell anyone.
( quietly ) The Federation's
more desperate than I thought.
( aloud ) I knew one day
you'd come crawling back to me.
-Now, get to work.
-Yes, Brother!
Jake?
Aren't you supposed to be on the Defiant?
I changed my mind.
There's a war going on and...
I'm a reporter.
This is where I belong.
But you're not safe here.
The Dominion knows I'm the Emissary's son.
If they hurt me,
they risk alienating their new friends,
the Bajorans.
I hope you're right.
So do I.
What the hell is Jake thinking?
Do we go back for him?
I can't risk the entire crew
for one man...
even though he is my son.
And whether I like it or not, he is a man,
capable of making his own choices.
Maintain current course.
Aye, Captain.
We should rendezvous with the Federation
task force in 48 hours.
And then what?
And then, we make the Dominion sorry
they ever set foot in the Alpha Quadrant.
Cadet, you took the words
right out of my mouth.
This is a great victory for Cardassia.
And the Dominion.
Over 50 ships lost...
our spacedocks on Torros III destroyed.
A victory perhaps, but a costly one.
We'll discuss the repercussions later.
Right now, I'm going to enjoy this moment.
Gentlemen,
on behalf of the Bajoran government--
And the Promenade
Merchants' Association...
I officially welcome you to Deep Space 9.
You mean... Terok Nor, don't you?
Founder, we are honored
by your decision to remain with us.
I'm not here as a Founder.
I'm the station's Chief of Security.
Whatever you say.
Nevertheless, having a God walk amongst us
is most gratifying.
I agree.
You... me...
the Major...
together again.
It should be most interesting.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'll be in my office.
( static and hissing )
It would appear
Captain Sisko was most efficient
in disabling the station.
It can be repaired.
And it will be.
But your first priority
is to dismantle that minefield.
Until we can bring in
reinforcements from the Gamma Quadrant,
our position here is vulnerable.
I'll deal with the minefields.
I assume Captain Sisko removed
or destroyed everything of value.
Not everything.
What is that?
A message... from Sisko.
I don't understand.
( chuckles )
He's letting me know...
He'll be back.