Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
O'BRIEN:
More Jem'Hadar ships
come through the
wormhole every week.
It must stop.
It's going to stop.
How do we keep them out?
We're going to mine
the entrance to the wormhole.
Prevent the Dominion
from bringing
any more reinforcements
to Cardassia.
Either you remove the mines,
or we will take
this station
from you...
and remove them ourselves.
Mr. Worf, all weapons
fire at will.
I've been waiting
for this moment
for five years.
We've lost main power
to the shields.
( yells )
What are your orders, Captain?
We've done
all we can here.
Notify all remaining
Starfleet personnel.
We're evacuating
the station.
I heard you're not
coming with us--
that you've been assigned
to Martok's ship.
It may be some time
before we see
each other again.
Worf, we may never
see each other again.
Dukat wanted
the station back.
He can have it.
And now, the continuation.
Cadet?
Long-range scanners show
no sign of Jem'Hadar ships.
Looks like they've broken off
the pursuit.
O'BRIEN:
I guess they got tired
of looking at our backs.
Three months
of bloody slaughter,
and what have we got
to show for it?
Not a damned thing.
Engage, retreat,
engage, retreat.
Just once, I
would've liked
to have gotten
a look at their backs.
Chief, that's enough.
Sorry, sir.
Nothing a little sleep
won't cure.
We could all use some sleep.
What has it been-- 78 hours?
Shouldn't we
have heard something
from the Seventh Fleet
by now?
DAX:
I wouldn't worry
just yet.
The Tyra system
is far enough away
that it'll be a day or two
before we get any message.
You think they could
stop the Dominion?
Damn right they can.
Somebody has to.
Ah, there you are.
I was beginning
to give up hope, Doctor.
I would think that all
those lunches we've shared
would have entitled me
to preferential treatment.
Look, I have 12
wounded officers and
crewman out there,
all of whom are in
a lot worse shape
than you, Garak.
Well, if you're trying
to cheer me up,
it's working.
I feel better already.
What happened?
I was studying some star charts
for Captain Sisko
during the last assault,
when I had a sudden
and rather violent encounter
with a bulkhead.
You'll live.
I wish I shared
your confidence.
I'm sure my
head will heal,
but the way this
war is going,
I wouldn't bet
on any of us
living to a ripe old age.
I admit the odds are not good,
but they could be worse.
Ah, let me guess.
You've used your
genetically enhanced brain
to calculate our
chances for survival.
It really wasn't
that difficult.
I simply started
with a binomial--
I'm really not
interested, Doctor.
Ever since it's become
public knowledge
that you're genetically
engineered,
you've used every
opportunity to show off.
I have nothing
to hide anymore.
I might as well use
what I have.
Well... what are
our chances?
Over 50 percent?
32.7.
I'm sorry I asked.
You're certain
about that figure?
Do you want me to take you
through the entire set
of calculations?
Not really.
"Genetically engineered,"
indeed.
Excuse me?
Well, look at you.
You act as if you haven't
a care in the world.
It's exactly that kind
of smug, superior attitude
that makes people like
you so... unpopular.
Are you trying
to insult me?
"A 32.7 percent chance
of survival"--
I call that insulting.
Don't take it
so personally, Garak.
It's strictly a matter
of mathematics.
No. It's strictly
a matter of our lives.
You're not genetically
engineered.
You're a Vulcan.
If I'm a Vulcan
then how do you explain
my boyish smile?
Not so boyish
anymore, Doctor.
DAX:
So where do you think
Starfleet will be
sending us next?
I don't know,
but if I have anything
to say about the matter,
we'll be going right back
to the front lines.
MARTOK:
Well said, Captain,
and my ship
will be at your side.
Worf!
Tell her.
Tell me what?
It can wait.
No! It cannot.
Raktajino.
It's been weighing heavily
on his mind.
What is it, Worf?
What's wrong?
It is about our wedding.
You're getting cold feet?
You have scheduled
the ritual sacrifice
of the targ
to occur after the wedding feast
has been served.
DAX:
We haven't
seen each other
for five weeks and that's
the first thing you say to me?
( quietly ):
We agreed it would be
a traditional ceremony.
( sighing )
Okay. Have it your way.
First, we'll shed blood,
and then we'll feast.
As it should be.
He has been unable
to talk of anything
else for days.
He's such a worrier.
SISKO:
Take it from me,
old man--
a small wedding
is the way to go.
Well, you get married
the way you want,
and I'll get married
the way I want.
I'll see you later,
Captain.
SISKO:
Try not to break
any bones.
Now that that's settled,
I'm going to take
care of this.
Klingons make great
warriors, but...
terrible doctors.
Captain...
Just the man
I wanted to see.
We've been ordered
to report to Starbase 375
for reassignment.
Something else, Doctor?
I have news of
the Seventh Fleet.
Go on.
Only 14 ships made it back
to our lines.
MARTOK:
Fourteen...
out of 112.
We can't keep taking
these kinds of
losses, sir,
not if we expect
to win this.
Thank you, Doctor.
That will be all.
I'll take a look
at that arm now.
DUKAT:
Permanent Documentation File,
Dukat, S.G.
Each day brings reports
of new victories.
The war continues to go well.
The enemy is retreating.
on almost all fronts.
It's only a matter of time
before the Federation
collapses
and Earth becomes
another conquered planet
under Dominion rule.
All in all, it's a good time
for Cardassia.
And the Dominion.
My dear Major Kira,
you have no idea
how it pleases me
to hear you say that.
Dukat,
the Major has
just given me
the most
wonderful news.
Bajorans are returning
to the station.
I'm well aware of it.
Then I'm sure you share
my delight
in knowing that life here
is returning to normal.
The shops are reopening.
The Promenade is abuzz
with activity once again.
The Habitat Ring echoes
with the laughter
of happy children.
I've doubled
security patrols
throughout the station.
Are such precautions
really necessary?
I've found that one
can't be too careful
when dealing
with the Bajorans.
What's the matter, Dukat?
Afraid we'll take the station
away from you again?
You're welcome
to try.
Come now, come now.
There's no need
for this petty bickering.
We're all
friends here.
Are we?
Of course we are,
and if you have
any suggestions, Major,
feel free to bring them
to me at any time.
Fine.
We'd like the station's Bajoran
security force reinstated.
I suppose you want us
to give them back
their weapons as well.
That's right.
The station
no longer requires
a Bajoran security force.
Our troops can handle
any problems that might arise.
The Federation and Bajor
always shared
equal responsibility
for station security.
I thought you said
that we would have
the same arrangement
with the Dominion.
After all,
we are all friends here...
aren't we?
Perhaps you should
reconsider your decision.
The order stands.
You may trust the Bajorans,
but I don't...
and until they earn my trust,
I prefer to keep
them unarmed.
And if you were in
my position, Major,
you would do
exactly the same thing.
Perhaps it would be best
to let the matter rest
for a while.
I'm sure in time we'll
be able to resolve
all these minor problems
to our mutual satisfaction.
I'll remember
you said that.
I'm sure you will.
One last thing...
Odo.
What about him?
( quietly ):
Is he aware
that I'm doing
everything I can
to strengthen the bond
between the Dominion
and the Bajoran people?
Why don't you ask him
yourself?
No, no. I wouldn't
want to bother him.
Good day, Major.
She's a fascinating
woman, isn't she?
I wouldn't know...
but I do know we
need her as an ally.
The Bajorans will never
be our allies.
Out.
Don't look
at him.
I'm telling you to leave.
Now!
I find him useful.
In the future...
it might be prudent
for you to include me
in all decisions
regarding station policy.
Now...
what about
the wormhole?
You assured me that
you would be able
to dismantle the minefield
within a month.
That was two months ago.
Well, I admit
the work is proceeding
more slowly than expected,
but as you know,
these are not ordinary mines.
Every time we deactivate
or destroy one of them,
its neighbor replicates
a new one.
We have to take down
that minefield
and reopen the wormhole.
And we will.
But there's no need for panic.
We are winning the war.
For the moment, yes,
but to defeat the Federation,
we're going to need
reinforcements
and new supplies
of ketracel-white...
soon.
Weyoun...
I said I will deal
with the minefield,
and I will.
Hmm.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Once again, I see
you're at your usual table.
It's amazing
how many of my customers
think of Quark's
as their second home.
I only wish I had
a holo-imager
so I could preserve
this warm and wonderful
moment of camaraderie.
Something
you could hang
on the wall
of your barracks.
Have you tried
the dabo tables?
I'm sure one
of my lovely hostesses
would be happy
to teach you the game.
I know...
a complimentary hour
in one of our
state-of-the-art holosuites.
Whatever
your desires,
I'm sure we can satisfy them.
Perhaps another time.
Enjoy the evening.
Tough crowd.
I'm telling you, Odo,
Dukat has only one thing
on his mind,
and that's revenge.
He can't stand
the thought
that Bajor
defeated Cardassia.
You think he wants to
reopen the labor camps?
Oh, eventually.
Well, then, I suppose
we should be grateful
that he has Weyoun
looking over his shoulder.
Maybe.
Weyoun's a hard one
to figure out.
I don't really
trust him, but...
I trust him
more than Dukat.
Weyoun knows
that it's
in the Dominion's
best interest
to honor its treaty
with Bajor.
They want to prove
to the rest of
the Alpha Quadrant
that they're true
to their word.
Weyoun asked me
about you.
He seemed very concerned
about what you
thought of him.
( scoffs )
I try not
to think of him.
He'd be hurt to hear
you say that.
I'll have to mention it
to him.
( chuckles )
I'm glad you
can still smile.
Ah, only
when I'm with you.
That's kind of
you to say.
No, it's true.
When I talk to you,
things don't seem as bad.
When I think of Dukat
in the Captain's office
or the fact that the Federation
seems to be losing this war,
and we're sitting here
doing nothing...
I share your frustration, Major,
but right now,
there's really nothing we can do
but bide our time.
It's like Captain Sisko said--
Bajor must be kept
out of the fighting.
And who am I to argue
with the Emissary?
QUARK:
Thanks for waiting.
Things have been
a little busier than expected.
This one's
on the house.
What do you want, Quark?
The usual--
peace, love, and understanding.
Not to mention
a generous profit margin,
which, I'm happy to say,
is looking more and more likely.
You know, I never
expected to say this,
but as occupations go,
this one's not so bad.
No, I suppose
that's true
if all you're worried about
is a monthly balance sheet.
I'm not just concerned
with profit, Major.
Look around.
Do you see any ghetto fences
dividing the Promenade?
Or exhausted
Bajoran slave laborers
sprawled on the ground
after a grueling day
in the ore-processing
center?
Do you hear
the cries of starving children?
I don't.
Now, don't
get me wrong.
I miss the Federation, too.
All I'm saying is
things could be a lot worse.
( sighs )
I hate to say this,
but he's right.
The Dominion seems
determined to prove
that it can be
a friend to Bajor.
If it's such
a good friend,
why are there
no Bajoran security officers
on the station?
I'm glad you made it back
in one piece, Ben.
I was lucky.
We lost a lot
of good people.
Yes, we did,
and we're going
to lose a lot more
before this is over.
I hope you'll find
this office satisfactory.
Office?
I wasn't aware
I'd be needing an office.
I thought I was here
for an assignment briefing.
I'm afraid
you're going to be here
for a lot longer
than you think, Captain.
As of right now,
you're no longer
in command of the Defiant.
Relieved of command?
Why?
Admiral Ross
didn't say.
He did say
we'll be getting
our new assignment
at 1600 hours.
Well, at least the crew
is staying together.
We are staying together,
aren't we?
You can count on it.
So what do you plan on doing
the next couple of hours?
I haven't given
it much thought.
Maybe now would be
a good time
to contact your father.
Maybe.
Benjamin, you haven't
spoken to him for months,
and Jake is
his grandson.
How do I explain
that I evacuated
every Federation citizen
off Deep Space 9
except his grandson?
You'll think of something.
You always do.
You did what?
Dad, it's not quite
as bad as it sounds.
You mean, you didn't leave
my grandson
at the mercy of a vicious,
bloodthirsty enemy?
Well... no.
I did.
Then it's certainly
just as bad as it sounds.
Dad, it was not my decision.
It was Jake's choice
to stay behind.
Oh, so now you're going
to blame this on Jake.
I'm not blaming Jake.
He's not a child anymore.
He's responsible
for his own actions.
I don't care who's responsible.
It's wrong, and I want him back.
And so do I.
Do you think he's all right?
I hope so.
I'll bring him back, Dad.
I promise.
When?
That I don't know.
It might be a while.
I'm about to be given
new orders,
and I don't know
where they're going to send me.
Tell them
you want to go get your son.
It's wartime.
It's not up to me.
I go where I'm sent.
( sighing )
How's the restaurant doing?
All right.
It's been three weeks
since I poisoned anyone.
Are things really as bad
as the news service claims?
Maybe worse.
Well, you certainly know how
to comfort a frightened old man.
You didn't raise me
to be a liar.
I raised you to be a chef,
for all the good it did me.
You know, there's something
I just don't understand.
You're always telling me
that space is big,
that it's an endless frontier
filled with infinite wonders.
It's true.
Well, if that's the case,
you would think it would be...
more than enough room
to allow people
to leave each other alone.
It just doesn't work that way.
It should, but it doesn't.
I better be going.
The lunch crowd's coming in.
You watch yourself, Ben...
and bring me back my grandson.
I will.
I love you.
I love you, too.
( breaks connection )
Hello.
Excuse me,
Mr. Weyoun.
Oh... please.
Uh, I prefer
just, uh... Weyoun.
That's the kind
of detail people
like to know.
Uh, would this
be a good time?
For what?
For the interview
we talked about--
you know, for the
Federation News Service.
Oh, ho, I'm afraid that
will be quite impossible.
Why?
Because I've read
your previous articles,
and they left me with
one inescapable conclusion--
you are biased
against the Dominion.
What-what gave
you that idea?
You keep referring to us
as the station's
"occupying force."
What's wrong
with that?
It has a negative
connotation.
All your articles are filled
with pejorative terminology,
which is why
I've been forced
to withhold
their transmission.
Are you telling me
that no one
from the Federation
read my reports?
If I don't send them,
they don't read them.
What about freedom
of the press?
Please tell me
you're not that naive.
The only reason
I stayed here
was to report on
the occupation.
You see,
there you go again.
This is not an occupation.
This is a Cardassian
station, Jake,
and I'm sure you're aware
there are no Dominion troops
on Bajor.
Why should there be?
We have a treaty with them.
They're our friends.
All right.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
anything by it.
If you want me
to send your articles
to the Federation,
you're going to have to provide
a more balanced perspective.
I won't write
Dominion propaganda.
I would never dream
of asking you to.
All I want is for you
to keep an open mind.
All right. My
mind is open.
Now can we do
the interview?
( chuckling )
All in good time.
You keep writing.
I'll keep reading.
Let's leave it
at that for now.
( chuckling ):
Good day, Jake.
Starfleet Intelligence
has discovered
what we believe to be
their main storage facility
for ketracel-white
in the Alpha Quadrant--
right here,
deep in Cardassian space.
We need to
destroy it.
Without the white
to sustain them,
the Jem'Hadar
won't be able to function.
Without the white,
the Jem'Hadar will die.
I won't shed any tears,
not if it
helps end this war.
It may be our only way to end
this war, short of surrendering.
How do you expect us to
infiltrate Cardassian territory
without the Defiant
and its cloaking abilities?
I was wondering
the same thing.
You won't need
a cloaking device.
We have something even better.
DAX:
A Jem'Hadar attack ship.
It's the one you captured
last year, Captain.
Now you get a chance
to see what it can do.
Do you even know
how to fly that thing?
Not yet, but I
intend to learn.
Guidance matrix, check.
Aft parabolic thrusters, check.
Sensor feed, check.
Chief.
Reactor core, check.
Induction stabilizers, check.
Phaser coils, check.
Nog.
Resonance emitters, check.
Subspace field grid, check.
Signal subprocessors, check.
I think.
You think?
We've been training
on this ship
for two weeks now.
I would like to put a Jem'Hadar
soldier on the Defiant
and see how well he does
after two weeks.
These controls
are very... different.
They take time
to get used to.
We don't have
any more time.
We're about
to take this ship
into enemy territory.
We don't want
any slip-ups.
I don't intend
to make any, Chief.
Good.
I still don't see
why we couldn't install
a few chairs on the Bridge.
Because this ship
wasn't designed for chairs.
Well, my feet
aren't designed
to stand
for long periods of time.
They get tired.
Maybe we should
leave you behind.
My feet might like that,
but I wouldn't.
It's not your feet
you need to worry about.
It's your stomach.
Have you noticed?
There isn't
a single food replicator
anywhere on this ship.
That shouldn't
be a problem.
Captain Sisko says
there'll be
plenty of field rations.
Trying eating field rations
for three weeks
and then tell me
it isn't a problem.
DAX:
You know what
is a problem?
No viewscreen.
Who builds a Bridge
without a window?
The same people who build a ship
without an Infirmary.
Here's a list of all the medical
supplies I brought on board.
They're in my quarters,
for want of a better space.
Well, don't worry.
We'll try not to have
any medical emergencies
while you're sleeping.
I'm so glad that you find
the lack of proper
medical facilities amusing,
but if trouble breaks out,
it's not a viewscreen
or a chair or even a sandwich
you'll be wanting.
It's a bio-bed
with a surgical
tissue regenerator.
Maybe, but right now,
I would settle
for a viewscreen.
Or a chair.
Or a sandwich.
All right, people,
prepare for departure.
All systems ready, sir.
Garak, come to see us off?
Uh, not quite.
I invited Mr. Garak
to join us.
Considering we're heading
into Cardassian territory,
I thought
he might prove useful.
Well, it's been
known to happen.
Pull up a chair.
We're cleared for departure,
sir.
Take us out, old man.
Aye, Captain.
Aft thrusters at one-half.
SISKO:
Bring us about.
DAX:
Just wanted
to make sure
everyone was awake.
We are now.
Just take it nice and easy,
all right?
I can try.
Set a course
for the Cardassian border,
heading 054 mark 093.
Warp six.
Yes, sir.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You wanted to see me?
I always want to see you, Major,
and therein lies
the problem.
It's been three months
since my return to this station,
and you and I have barely spent
any time with one another.
Oh, I know you could point out
the various meetings
we've attended together,
but... they never seem
to offer us
the opportunity to venture
beyond station business.
I don't have time for this.
Major!
I haven't dismissed you yet.
What do you want
from me, Dukat?
Come now, Major.
Have the last three months
been that bad?
Is that what you want?
Is that why I'm here?
To flatter you?
To tell you what
a good job you've done
and how happy we all
are to have you back?
Sarcasm doesn't
become you, Major.
It's your directness
that I've always found
most appealing.
Dukat, I got better things
to do
than to stand around
and help you play out
one of your little fantasies.
You feel I've betrayed you.
Not just me.
Everyone.
Even your own people.
Cardassia was on the edge
of an abyss, Major.
The war with the Klingons
left us a third-rate power.
My people had
lost their way.
I've made them strong again.
At what price?
You sold Cardassia
to the Dominion.
Yes--
a high price, to be sure,
but look what we're getting
in return.
The Alpha Quadrant itself.
We'll see about that.
Yes, we will.
Oh... I could make things very
pleasant for you here, Kira.
You could start by doing
something about your breath.
I'm a patient man.
I can wait.
Wait for what?
What do you think
is going to happen here, Dukat?
That you're going
to wear me down
with your charming personality?
That I'm going
to be swept off my feet
by that insincere smile?
Are you really so deluded
that you
actually believe
that we're going to have
some kind
of intimate relationship?
Oh, we already do.
( chuckling )
Good day, Major.
I have work to do.
BASHIR:
There.
I wish I had more time
to study the side effects
of wearing that headset.
At least we know one
side effect-- headaches.
Well, the headsets
were designed
to be worn by the Vorta and
the Jem'Hadar, not humans.
Captain, may I make
a suggestion?
Only if you talk softly.
We saw Dukat...
Shh.
( softly ):
wearing one of these headsets
during the attack
on Deep Space 9.
Perhaps Cardassian physiology
is more compatible.
Are you volunteering?
I suppose I am.
This ship is equipped
with two of them.
If I wore one,
then you wouldn't have to.
At least, not all the time.
I agree with
Garak, Captain.
The less you wear
it, the better.
Garak.
Ah, it's like having
a viewscreen
inside your brain.
( console beeping )
NOG:
Sir...
there's a Federation ship
off our starboard bow
bearing 157 mark 095.
It's the USS Centaur.
That's Charlie
Reynolds' ship.
I see it.
Ah.
Cadet, open a channel
to the Centaur.
I can't.
Our com system's down.
Perhaps we should consider
returning fire.
We can't do that.
They're Starfleet.
Well, you tell
them, not us.
We better do something.
Dax, get us
across the border, maximum warp.
I hope Charlie Reynolds
knows better
than to follow us
into Dominion territory.
How long before we
cross the border?
We just did.
The Centaur's still with us.
Charlie never did know
when to quit.
I hope he knows
what he's doing.
The question is:
Do we know what we're doing?
Captain, that last hit
damaged one of our
guidance thrusters.
Drop us out of warp.
Come about.
Prepare to return fire.
Yes, sir.
The Centaur has dropped
out of warp.
Target their weapons array.
Avoid their engines.
I don't want to leave
Charlie out here stranded
on the wrong side
of the border.
We're coming about
for another pass.
Charlie likes to swing
for the fences so stay in tight.
Attack pattern omega.
DAX:
The Centaur
is going into warp.
They're heading back
to Federation space.
Yes.
Nice work, Chief.
I didn't know
I'd scored a direct hit.
Maybe you didn't.
I'm picking up three Jem'Hadar
ships headed this way.
He must have seen them.
They went right by us.
Without even bothering
to say hello.
They're too busy
chasing the Centaur.
Do you think Reynolds
will outrun them?
Charlie's been
in tight spots before.
He'll make it.
I wish we could help.
We can't.
Chief, get our com system
back on line.
Return to course.
Warp seven.
Yes, sir.
You should have seen the
arrogant, smug look on his face.
He was in control.
And there was nothing
that I could do about it.
The war isn't over yet,
but as far as Dukat is
concerned, he's already won.
I would love to show him
that he's wrong.
Well, for the moment, at least,
I'm afraid he has won.
Look at me.
I don't know why I bother
to sit here every day.
I don't even have
a security force
to patrol the Promenade.
Then ask for one.
Demand that they reinstate
your Bajoran deputies.
Dukat will never agree to that.
Forget about Dukat.
Go to Weyoun.
He'll listen to you.
As far as
he's concerned,
you are a God,
and that gives you power.
But what good is power
if you're not willing to use it?
JEM'HADAR SOLDIERS:
We pledge our loyalty
to the Founders
from now until death.
Then receive this reward
from the Founders.
May it keep you strong.
You enjoy that, don't you?
That constant reminder
that you're their master.
The Founders
are the masters.
I am merely
their servant,
as are the Jem'Hadar...
and you.
That may be...
but even amongst servants,
someone has to be
in charge, hmm?
That is exactly the
kind of observation
I've come to expect
from you, Dukat.
Interesting, yet
somewhat petty.
Forgive the interruption,
but he insisted
on seeing you
immediately.
Founder, I'm honored
by your visit.
Is there some way
I can be of service?
I want my Bajoran security
officers reinstated.
Consider it done.
From now on,
they'll be responsible
for security
on the Promenade.
I don't see any
problem with that.
I do.
This is between
me and Odo.
I'll thank you
to keep out of it.
I'll have
my officers report
to the armory
within the hour.
Now that I've done
something for you,
perhaps there's
something
you'd consent
to do for me.
A member of the station's
Ruling Council.
You?
Along with Weyoun
and Dukat.
Now, I'll have a voice
in station policy.
You sure this
is a good idea?
Dukat thought it
was a terrible idea.
You should have
seen his face
when Weyoun offered
me the position.
But don't you see
that Weyoun is using you?
Your presence
on the Council
validates the Dominion
control of the station.
I thought we
were using him.
I know the danger, Major.
I've had to, to walk
this line before
during the Cardassian
occupation.
I can do it again,
but this time,
I won't be alone.
I'll have you to help me.
That's right, you will.
Then this is
a victory after all.
I suppose it is...
but for some reason,
it just doesn't
feel like one.
GARAK:
The ship ahead
just transmitted a message
to the asteroid
storage facility.
They're requesting to be
resupplied with ketracel-white.
Looks like we've come
to the right place.
The ship beamed down
110 empty canisters.
Now the storage facility
is beaming up 110 full ones.
Everything ready, Chief?
O'BRIEN:
I've got 83 empty canisters
standing by,
and one not-so-empty.
90 isotons
of enriched ultritium.
It should take care
of the entire storage facility
and everything else
within 800 kilometers.
Which means we have to be
900 kilometers away
before the bomb goes off.
The other ship is leaving orbit.
Dax.
The entire exchange
took 92.3 seconds.
I've asked for
84 canisters
of ketracel-white.
( communications beep )
Excellent.
They're acknowledging
my request.
Chief, set the detonator
for three minutes.
O'BRIEN:
Detonator set.
Three minutes?
If it takes 92.3 seconds
to make the exchange,
that doesn't give us
much time, sir.
That doesn't give the
Jem'Hadar much time
to detect the
explosive either.
Commander, beam
down the canisters.
Canisters away.
I hope whoever's
in charge down there
hasn't taken a lunch break.
The Jem'Hadar
don't eat, Nog.
That's good.
How do we know
they're Jem'Hadar?
Relax, Cadet.
Everything's on schedule.
They've just beamed
84 canisters of white
into our cargo bay.
I've acknowledged
receipt
and requested clearance
for departure.
Good. Prepare
to go to warp.
Standing by.
Captain, I think
we have a problem.
They've just raised
the security net.
Repeat our request
for clearance.
They're not responding.
If they don't
shut down that net
before the bomb goes off,
we don't have a chance.
One minute, 30 seconds
to detonation.
Do you think
they found the bomb?
I doubt it, not this fast.
Then why aren't they
letting us go?
That's a good question.
Captain, they're responding.
They're ordering
us to stand by.
For what?
They're not saying.
One minute, 15 seconds.
Chief, can we punch a hole
in the security net?
Sure, but it'll take
a couple of minutes.
We don't have a
couple of minutes.
What if we disable the
net's power generator?
The explosion will do that.
Well, that won't
do us much good.
One minute.
Maybe it will.
When the generator's
destroyed,
the net'll come down.
All we have to do
is to time it
so that we're
moving fast enough
at the moment
of detonation
to avoid being caught
in the explosion.
But not so fast
that we smash into the net
before it's deactivated.
It's tricky.
Not if we time it right.
Let's see... a radial geodesic
in a 39 Cochrane warp field
contracts normal space
at a rate of--
We have to go to full impulse
1.3 seconds
before the bomb detonates.
Dax?
The computer
agrees with Julian.
Of course it does.
They think alike.
Turning over
piloting controls
to the main computer.
Set.
Time?
22 seconds until the explosion.
22 seconds.
That's plenty of time.
See, Cadet? There was
nothing to worry about.
Must have gone off early.
Dax, get us out of here!
Well, not quite
according to plan,
but I'm sure Starfleet
will be quite satisfied
with the results.
I agree, Mr. Garak.
Well done, old man.
How bad is it, Chief?
It doesn't look good.
I'm going to have to switch
to auxiliary life support.
Deflectors are down,
guidance system's shot, and...
And what?
The core matrix is fried.
We don't have warp drive.
Uh, forgive my ignorance,
but if we don't have warp drive,
how long is it going
to take us
to reach the closest
Federation starbase?
A long time, Mr. Garak.
How long?
17 years, two months
and three days...
give or take an hour.