SISKO:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
O'Brien needed three days
to restore main power
to our commandeered
Dominion ship
but he's not going to get them.
Sensors have detected
two Jem'Hadar fighters
heading our way,
and without main power
our chances of survival
are slim to none.
Try it now.
Reroute the
damned gyrodyne
through the damned
thruster array.
Got it.
Mr. Garak, where are
those ships now?
Bearing 310 mark 215,
still closing.
O'BRIEN:
Nog, did you reroute
that damned gyrodyne?
NOG:
I'm trying, but
the damned thruster array
won't take the input.
Try the lateral
impulse thrusters.
And watch your mouth.
Access the auxiliary core
through the starboard
engineering console.
I've already tried that.
Still no power to
weapons or shields.
Dax, there's
a dark matter nebula
60 degrees above the bow.
Can we reach it?
Yes, but that nebula's
never been charted.
We don't know what's in there.
The Jem'Hadar ships
are entering weapons range.
Dax!
Get us into
the nebula.
Full impulse!
( yells )
Sisko to Bashir,
medical emergency.
Helm control's gone.
Okay, all right.
You'll be feeling
better any second now.
She's got a puncture
of the right abdominal cavity.
It looks as thought the symbiont
may have been injured.
Sensors are gone,
impulse engines off-line.
In fact, everything's off-line.
Emergency power's
holding for now.
Mr. Garak, take a look outside.
Just a moment.
SISKO:
Chief, what happened?
O'BRIEN:
I don't know.
We must have been hit
by some kind
of gravitational
spike in the--
Oh, no!
Mr. Garak?
Hold on!
We have established
a defense perimeter
around the entrance
to the cavern.
I have sent two patrols
to reconnoiter the shoreline
in both directions.
The Vorta's condition
has worsened.
He will die soon.
What about the First
and the Second?
I vaporized their bodies myself
and redistributed
their equipment
to the rest of the men.
You are now the First.
No. I questioned
the Vorta's orders.
He will not forget that.
As long as he lives,
I will remain Third.
You were right
to question him.
If he had not ordered us
into the nebula two days ago
we would not have crashed.
It was not my place.
Remember,
obedience brings victory.
And victory is life.
Until we reestablish
communications
we will hold this world
for the Dominion.
And if we cannot
reestablish communications?
Then we will hold this world
for the Dominion...
until we die.
( coughing )
( coughing and gasping )
Cadet, this is no time
to lie down on the job.
( coughs )
SISKO:
Heave!
( all groaning )
One more, now--
heave!
( all sighing and panting )
All right, how is she?
She's stable for now.
Garak! I need a hand.
Oh, no.
What?
I don't believe it.
I tore my pants.
You... you tore your pants.
Yeah, I tore my pants.
( chuckling )
( laughing ):
I guess...
I guess I'm really
in trouble now, huh?
( all laughing )
COMPUTER:
The time is 0500 hours.
( call button beeps )
Thank you, Mavek.
VORTA:
This must be
quite gratifying for you
but I've decided not to give you
the pleasure of watching me die
in this foul-smelling cavern.
I intend to live.
I understand.
How long until we've
reestablished communications?
Seventh Yak'Talon estimates that
it will take at least ten days
before we can attempt
a low-power test.
Ten days.
( coughs )
It is time for the white.
( groans )
Third Remata'Klan...
can you vouch
for the loyalty of your men?
We pledge our loyalty
to the Founders
from now until death.
Then receive this reward
from the Founders.
May it keep
you strong.
Only one?
Keep your place.
This case of white must last
until we're rescued--
at least ten days
possibly more.
I will ration
the supply.
Don't worry.
I am the Vorta.
I will take care of you all.
( coughs weakly )
GARAK:
Lucky for you, it
ripped on the seam.
Can you fix it?
Unlucky for you
my sewing kit went
down with the ship.
WOMAN:
Maybe someone could go get it.
The ship's only about 500
meters below the surface.
O'BRIEN:
How long can you hold
your breath, Cadet?
Madame, your pants
are ready.
Your boots and vest will
take a little longer.
While you wait
I might suggest
that you browse
through the hotel's
gift shop.
No, thank you
but I would like
to lodge a complaint.
Hmm?
This bed is
as hard as a rock.
I will make
note of that.
What's the prognosis?
Guarded, but good.
The bleeding's stopped
and I've repaired all
the internal injuries.
The damage
to the symbiont
is a little harder
to diagnose.
Given enough rest
I think they'll both
make a full recovery.
In other words, I'm going to be
staring at this cave ceiling
for the rest
of my stay.
Lucky for you,
they have 24-hour
room service.
( giggles, then gasps in pain)
I will get you
out of here, old man, I promise.
I'm going to hold you
to that one, Benjamin.
( tricorders beeping softly )
What are you doing?
Following orders.
Captain told us to scan the area
for fresh water and vegetation--
You know precisely
what I mean.
You're deliberately
staying behind me
and I want
to know why.
Does this have anything to do
with that unfortunate business
between you and me last year?
You tied me up
and threatened to kill me.
There were extenuating
circumstances.
It happened.
So you can either stay in front
of me or walk beside me
but I won't turn my back
on you again.
Cadet, there may be
hope for you yet.
( beeping loudly )
What is it?
I'm not sure, but--
Now I'm sure.
How many others
are there in your unit?
Nog--
Cadet Third Class,
serial number CX-937--
Shut up.
As I tried to explain
to your men
my name is Kamar,
and I'm a member
of the Cardassian
Intelligence Bureau--
what used to be called
the Obsidian Order.
A week ago, as I was
performing my duties
in the glorious service
of the Founders
I was captured
by the USS Centaur.
I was held aboard
one of their shuttles
when we were forced--
Excuse me, Mr. Kamar--
if that's really your name--
but if you're one of our allies,
why were you wearing this?
Ah.
I was hoping you weren't going
to ask me about that.
I only have one
further question for you.
Is there a doctor in your unit?
Yes.
Garak!
Don't be too hard on him,
young man.
He just saved your life.
Take them to a secure area.
( breathing shallowly )
Third...
I have a mission for you.
I want you to find
the Starfleet unit
but do not engage them.
Locate them...
assess their strength
and then report back to me.
I understand.
No, you don't.
But that's all right.
It's not important
that you understand--
only that you carry out
my instructions precisely.
Obedience brings victory.
Yes...
yes, it does.
Go.
JAKE:
I understand
that a decision's been made
to send 4,000 Dominion
facilitators down to Bajor.
Would you care to elaborate?
It's only 400, and how
did you hear about that?
The official announcement
isn't scheduled
until tomorrow.
I hear things.
So could you
elaborate?
My readers want to know
what's going on.
You don't have any readers.
Weyoun is still blocking
the transmission
of your stories.
For now, but what
if he changes his mind?
Don't you want to explain
what's going on here
to the outside world?
Ever since
the war started
Bajor's been
completely cut off
from all outside trade.
We've had nowhere to turn
for things like spare parts
or medical supplies, nowhere--
except the Dominion.
So a group of facilitators is
going to Bajor for a few months
to provide
some technical
assistance.
How do you respond to critics
like Vedek Yassim
who say that by welcoming
a group of Vorta to Bajor
you're taking
the first step
towards Dominion
occupation?
I have been assured
that the facilitators
will be unarmed
and unaccompanied
by any Jem'Hadar soldiers.
Odo, do you have any concerns
that by joining the Ruling
Council here on the station
you're validating
the occupation?
The Dominion doesn't need
my validation.
They're here, and
they're not leaving--
not without a fight,
at least.
Are you finished?
Almost, almost.
Will either of you
be attending
the demonstration
tomorrow?
The what?
Vedek Yassim has organized
a demonstration
on the Promenade
tomorrow afternoon
to protest
the Dominion occupation
of the station.
That's all the excuse
Dukat will need
to order a new
security crackdown.
I'll talk to Yassim.
So, you're going to abolish
the right to protest
here on the station?
Hey, I'm not trying
to accuse you personally
of anything.
I'm just asking questions.
I think this interview
is over.
I couldn't agree more.
( sighs )
Wrong question,
Jake.
O'BRIEN:
I might be able to hard-wire
one of our combadges
into this sensor array.
That would give us
a crude transmitter,
but no power source.
What about draining
one of our phasers?
I thought about that,
but I need a converter
to bridge the two power cells,
and I can't build a converter
without an ion-exchange
matrix.
Captain, I think
we may have a problem.
Garak and Nog
haven't reported in yet
and they're not
answering my hails.
Captain, there's a group
of life-forms up in the cliffs.
Range 75 meters,
elevation 30 meters.
SISKO:
That's where I'd be.
Are they Jem'Hadar?
I think so.
Well, let's not
make it easy for them.
Tell the Chief to head toward
that large outcropping of rocks
at ten o'clock.
Walk, don't run.
( quietly ):
Chief...
we need to make
for those rocks up ahead.
I can't take it!
Terminate fire!
Terminate!
( weapons fire continues )
You have been ordered
to stop firing!
Your orders were clear.
You were not
to engage the enemy.
Who fired first?
I did.
You are reduced to Sixth.
You will shroud
and return to base camp.
I am no longer able
to shroud myself.
( weapons fire continues )
You, you.
Provide suppression fire
as we withdraw.
Understood.
Withdraw!
Remata'Klan
I regret my
disobedience.
Are they pulling out?
Looks that way.
Why aren't they camouflaged?
That's a good question.
Let's hope the answer is
something in our favor.
Cease fire!
VORTA:
Why were my orders disobeyed?
Lack of white produces
anxiety among us.
One man
could not restrain himself
when he saw the enemy.
Which man?
I have dealt with the matter.
I asked for his name!
He is my responsibility.
His name!
I may not be First,
but I am the unit leader.
You may discipline me.
But only I discipline the men.
That is the order of things.
Very well.
I'll leave him to you.
Dismissed.
You've done well, Third.
You may yet become First.
Now...
I have a new task for you.
The Dominion is evil
and the Prophets tell us
that evil must be opposed.
You'll get no argument
from me, Vedek
but protests and demonstrations
aren't going to change anything.
They're just going to cause
trouble for everyone.
Then what would you have us do
to oppose the Dominion?
I...
I don't think there's anything
you or the other Vedeks
can do right now.
I see.
Then as a Bajoran
Liaison Officer
what will you be doing
to fight the Dominion?
Fighting isn't an option.
This is different than
the Cardassian occupation.
Is it?
The Cardassians are in control
of the station.
Bajoran freedoms are being
curtailed one by one.
And soon the first wave
of alien troops will be
landing on our world.
We're talking about
unarmed Vorta facilitators.
They come in, they do their job
and they're gone.
Can't you see
what is happening to you?
You're becoming an apologist
for them, a defender of evil.
What will it take
to make you act, Kira?
To stop accepting them
and start fighting back?
Vedek, you...
you just don't understand.
You are right.
I don't.
Maybe tomorrow...
we will both understand.
We'll set up three
defensive positions.
You and Ensign Gordon
on the south ridge.
Lieutenant Neeley
near the lava tube.
Bashir and I are
in the dunes.
I'll stay here
and guard my clothes.
( on communicator )
Neeley to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
A Jem'Hadar soldier has just
approached my position, sir.
He says he wants
to talk to you... alone.
NEELEY:
Sir?
I'm Captain
Benjamin Sisko.
Third Remata'Klan.
Two members of your unit
are being held
at our base camp.
We'll exchange them for
you and your doctor.
Why do you need a doctor?
The Vorta has been
severely wounded.
And why me?
The Vorta wishes
to speak with you.
Sounds like he wants to trade
two low-ranking prisoners
for two more valuable ones.
Would you make
a deal like that?
No.
Then why should I?
You shouldn't.
You're not a very good
negotiator, are you?
I was not sent
to negotiate.
I was instructed only
to deliver the terms.
I see.
Well, then, I want to talk
to someone
who can negotiate.
I want to speak
with your First.
There is no First.
I take it there's
no Second either.
I command the unit.
Under the Vorta.
It must be hard...
for a soldier
to take orders from a Vorta.
The Vorta command the Jem'Hadar.
That is the order of things.
Obedience brings victory.
I was on a mission
with the Jem'Hadar once--
before the war, of course.
Oh, they were good,
tough, professional.
It was an honor
to serve with them.
But their Vorta, he...
was something different--
manipulative
treacherous...
trusted by neither side.
In the end...
he was killed...
by the Jem'Hadar First.
Surprised?
Such things have
been known to happen
but they are rare,
and only occur
in units that have
lost discipline.
Oh, you mean like a unit
marooned on the shores
of a deserted planet.
The Vorta has instructed me
to give you his assurance
that neither you nor
your doctor will be harmed
and you will both
be free to leave
at the end of your meeting.
What is your response?
The word of a Vorta carries
very little weight with me.
Can I have your assurance
that we'll be free
to go, Remata'Klan?
I have been ordered
to let you go free
after your meeting.
You can be assured that
I will obey that order.
Very well.
We'll make the trade
in one hour.
Agreed.
Sounded like you
were actually
getting through to him
for a minute there.
You can't break through
all that Dominion
conditioning
in just one conversation.
Do you really think you can
turn him against his Vorta?
I don't know.
But there were at least
seven Jem'Hadar soldiers
up on that ridge
this morning--
say at least two more
at their base camp
guarding their prisoners
and their Vorta.
Without Nog and Mr. Garak
on our side
that gives them almost
a two-to-one advantage.
I think I'd like
to check out now.
So would I, old man.
You may go.
Now, don't get too
far ahead, Nog.
We don't want
to startle anyone.
Ah, good afternoon,
Captain, Doctor.
SISKO:
Are you two all right?
GARAK:
Perfect.
How are you?
BASHIR:
Felt better.
Anything yet?
Not yet.
There are two Vedeks inside,
but we've seen no indication
they intend
to leave the shrine.
What about Yassim?
She hasn't shown up.
Let's hope she doesn't.
The last thing
I want to do
is start arresting
Bajoran civilians
here on the Promenade.
Don't think there's
going to be any story
here for you
today, Jake.
You sure?
I got a message
from Vedek Yassim
saying the protest was
starting at exactly 1400.
It certainly doesn't
look like it.
MAN:
What's she doing?!
Evil must be opposed.
( moans )
Captain Sisko...
my name is Keevan.
We have a lot to talk about.
BASHIR:
Not for a while
you don't.
He needs immediate surgery.
Now?
I don't think I have any choice.
I am a doctor.
I'm not going
to harm him.
( Keevan sighs )
They're not here
to protect me.
They've just never seen
what the inside
of a Vorta looks like.
COMPUTER:
The time is 0500 hours.
Thank you, Mavek.
How was the show?
Informative.
( sighs heavily )
Ah, I am alive.
No self-diagnosis, please.
I'm the doctor here.
Your internal
hemorrhaging
has stopped.
Your free-collagen levels
are dropping.
Tissue growth factors
have stabilized nicely
and there's a 50 percent rise
in cell oxygenation.
You... are alive.
( moans )
Careful.
Your insides are
being held together
by cellular micro-sutures,
and... a lot of hope.
Leave us.
And take your men
with you.
May I have that case, please?
( labored breathing )
There are ten Jem'Hadar soldiers
on this planet, Captain...
and that is
the only vial
of ketracel-white we have left.
When it's gone, my hold
over them will be broken
and they'll become
nothing more
than senseless,
violent animals.
They'll kill
everyone they can...
me, you, the rest of your men...
and finally turn on each other.
Why are you
telling us this?
I'm ordering the Jem'Hadar
to attack your base camp
in the morning.
But I will
provide you
with their precise plan
of attack.
You should be able
to kill them all.
They're your own men.
Yes.
You still haven't answered
my question.
Why are you doing this?
That... that's
a communications system.
It needs repair
but I'm willing to bet
that you've brought
one of those
famed Starfleet engineers
who can turn rocks
into replicators.
He should have
a lot more success
at repairing it than a Jem'Hadar
suffering from withdrawal.
Once you've
taken care
of the Jem'Hadar...
I'll give you the com system
and surrender to you...
as a prisoner of war.
And you spend the war
resting comfortably
as a Starfleet POW
while your men lie
rotting on this planet.
I see we understand each other.
I'm going to order the Jem'Hadar
to attack your
position tomorrow
regardless of whether
you agree to my terms or not.
So you can either kill them...
or they'll kill you.
Either way...
they're coming.
And when they've reached
this point
we'll have them in a crossfire.
They won't have a chance.
Now, that is the point.
In case you've forgotten,
we're in a war.
There are
rules, Garak
even in war.
Correction--
humans have rules in war.
Rules that tend to make victory
a little harder to achieve,
in my opinion.
So we just... shoot them down?
They wouldn't
hesitate
if the situation was reversed.
NOG:
But we're not
the Jem'Hadar.
It is our duty to--
This isn't a vote!
The decision's mine.
And Mr. Garak is right--
we are at war.
Given the choice
between us and them
there is no choice.
Let's move out.
I'd say good luck
but I... I don't think
you're going to need it.
Say it anyway,
old man.
I'm still hoping there's
another way out of this.
In that case...
good luck, Benjamin.
Damar has been trying
to contact you
for the past five hours.
I keep going over it
and over it in my mind.
And I can't
believe that...
that I stood there...
ready to use force
to stop a protest
against the Dominion.
Me.
When I was in the
resistance, I despised
people like me.
I'm a collaborator, Odo.
That's not true.
You're doing exactly
what Captain Sisko
wanted you and the rest
of Bajor to do--
remain neutral and stay
out of the fighting.
We used to have a saying
in the resistance:
If you're not fighting them,
you're helping them.
Half the Alpha
Quadrant is out there
right now, fighting
for my freedom
but not me.
What am I doing?
Eating a full meal
every day
sleeping in a soft bed--
even write reports
for the murderers
who run this station.
These are difficult
times for everyone.
Do you think
it's easy for me
to sit down with Dukat
and Weyoun every day
while they plot the destruction
of the Federation?
Odo...
I'm not pointing
a finger at you.
I'm the one who told you
to get more involved
in the first place.
No, this is about me.
This is about being able
to get up in the morning
and look in the mirror
and not feel nauseated
by what I see.
Yassim was right.
I have to do something.
I have to start
to fight back.
That would be a mistake.
Active resistance will
trigger a crackdown--
Odo...
I don't want to end up
fighting you, too...
but if I have to...
I will.
( sighs )
All right.
But let's find
a more discreet place
to plan the new resistance.
SISKO:
Remata'Klan!
I want to talk!
Agreed!
Hold this position.
Do not fire
unless they do.
Understood.
There's no way
out of this canyon
and we have phasers locked
on every one of you.
It appears you have
a decisive advantage.
To fight a battle
under these circumstances
would serve no purpose.
I'm prepared to offer terms.
Hear me out!
I know you need
more ketracel-white.
My doctor can
sedate your men
and keep them alive
until we're rescued.
After that, we can put you
in medical stasis
until we secure
a new supply.
The Vorta did not give me
the option to surrender.
Keevan's betrayed you!
He gave us your entire plan
of attack last night.
It was obvious that approaching
your position from this canyon
was a deliberate
tactical error on his part.
You knew?
I suspected.
Despite what Keevan may think
the Jem'Hadar are often
one step ahead of the Vorta.
You can still stay
one step ahead.
Surrender.
I have my orders.
Keevan doesn't deserve
the unwavering loyalty
you're giving him.
He does not have to earn
my loyalty, Captain.
He has had it from the moment
I was conceived.
I am a Jem'Hadar.
He is a Vorta.
It is the order of things.
Do you really want
to give up your life
for the order of things?
It is not my life
to give up, Captain.
And it never was.
What'd he say?
All the wrong things.
Our death is glory
to the Founders.
O'BRIEN:
Captain?
You know, Captain
if I had had just
two more vials
of white...
you never would've had a chance.
Chief!
Get this...
Take him back to base camp
then get to work
on that com system.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant Neeley!
Sir?
Form a burial detail.
Aye, sir.