Cadet.
Continuing to emit
distress signals
on all frequencies, sir.
Chief.
We're still venting plasma.
Any ship
within 100 million kilometers
will know we're here...
and that we're not going
anywhere.
We have company, Captain.
Two Dominion ships
heading this way
bearing 197 mark 135.
They'll have us in weapons range
in 22 seconds.
Shields?
Shields at 30 percent.
Phaser banks?
The entire weapons array
is off-line.
Now we find something
to hold onto.
Shields are down to 20 percent.
Now?
Now. Shields up,
engines at full impulse.
Power to main phasers.
Target locked.
Fire!
Cadet, are there any other
Dominion ships out there?
None that I can see.
This is the Captain speaking.
All hands, stand down.
Good job, people.
We're being hailed
by the Rotarran.
Commander Worf
wants to speak to you.
On screen.
Well done, Captain.
You were a very effective decoy.
How about next time
we switch roles?
That way, I can rescue you.
You may have to wait awhile,
Captain.
We've just received orders
from Starfleet Command.
All ships in this sector to
pull back to Starbase 375.
Fall back again.
Engage, retreat.
I tell you, that's becoming
our favorite tune.
Well, we better think
of a new tune fast
or the only song
we're going to be singing
is "Hail
the Conquering Dominion."
I wouldn't start learning
those lyrics just yet, Doctor.
Worf, we'll see you
at Starbase 375.
I will be waiting.
Set a course
for these coordinates.
Warp seven.
I don't know
what all you brass hats
in Starfleet Command
are thinking
but take it
from a simple field officer...
we're not going to win this war
by running away from the enemy.
I know that.
Benjamin, troop morale
is at an all-time low.
Even the Klingons
are starting to wonder
if we can defeat the Dominion.
We need a victory...
a big victory...
and we need it soon.
I couldn't agree with you more.
Then do something about it.
I already have.
In fact, I'm presenting a plan
to Starfleet Command
at 0800 tomorrow.
What plan?
We're going to retake
Deep Space 9.
Everything appears
to be perfectly normal.
I'm sorry, Garak.
Well, keep looking, Doctor.
Whatever Starfleet put in there
is very well-hidden.
Ridiculous.
Well, that's easy
for you to say, Chief.
You don't know them
as well as I do.
These are desperate people.
Garak, you're not going
to get any of us to believe
that Starfleet Intelligence
has implanted some kind
of neural transponder
in your brain
to monitor your thoughts.
I would have if I were them.
In fact, when I was
conducting interrogations
for the Obsidian Order,
I did a lot worse.
I'm sure you did.
They are not interrogating
you, Mr. Garak...
they are debriefing.
There is a difference.
Not from where I'm sitting.
Oh, I'll have
a raktajino, Julian.
And a raktajino.
Look, Garak,
we are at war with the Dominion.
Cardassia is part
of the Dominion.
You are a Cardassian
and, at one time, you were
a fairly important one.
Of course
Starfleet Intelligence
is going to press you
for specifics.
They need to know
everything you know.
Any small detail
could prove extremely important.
Well, take it from me...
it's a lot more fun
asking questions
than answering them.
All things considered
I'd rather be on the Defiant
with all of you.
Oh, believe me, you
haven't been missing much.
Hopefully, all of that's
about to change.
Do you think Starfleet Command
will approve Sisko's plan?
Well, we'll find out
soon enough.
He's in there
presenting it right now.
Here's to retaking the castle.
And planting our flag
on its battlements once again.
You two have spent too much time
in the holosuites.
By putting together
a task force comprised
of elements of the Second,
Fifth and Ninth Fleets
I believe we can retake
Deep Space 9...
the most important piece
of real estate
in the Alpha Quadrant.
Your plan, Captain Sisko,
is not without merit.
However, I remain skeptical.
The Dominion will undoubtedly
send a large fleet to stop you.
And it will divert their forces
and slow their advance
into Federation territory.
As well as leave
their flank vulnerable.
Which will give us a chance
to be on the offensive
for a change.
There's one thing
that still concerns me.
What's that, Admiral?
Earth.
You've left it
a very tempting target.
Earth will still be defended
by the Third Fleet.
But what if you're wrong
and the Dominion
doesn't commit its forces
to protect Deep Space 9?
What if, instead, they launch
a full-scale assault on Earth?
If we follow the plan
you're proposing
we'll never be able
to get reinforcements
there in time.
The Dominion won't attack Earth.
How can you be sure?
Because Earth isn't the key
to the Alpha Quadrant...
the wormhole is.
And whoever controls
Deep Space 9
controls the wormhole.
Unbelievable.
Amazing.
What nerve.
Morn, you do have a problem
but lucky for you,
the solution is simple.
You're a grown man,
and if you don't want
to attend your mother's
birthday party
you don't have to.
And if she keeps
whining about it
just remind her there's a war on
and you have things to do.
Another ale?
Um... uh...
here, uh...
it's on the house.
Major, you ready?
Now?
Right now.
All right, but I don't think
it'll do any good.
I keep telling myself
that Odo never meant
to have Rom arrested.
It was all a mistake...
bad timing, bad luck.
I thought that, too, at first.
I have known Odo a long time.
He's not a collaborator.
Then why is your brother
still in a holding cell?
We're here to see Odo.
The Founders are
not to be disturbed.
Odo will make
an exception for us.
There are no exceptions.
I'd like to hear that from Odo.
I'm sorry, Major,
but you're wasting your time.
His orders were quite clear.
He doesn't want to see anyone...
not until his guest has left.
And how long has his guest
been visiting?
As far as I know,
the female changeling
has not left his quarters
for three days.
Step away from the door,
Ferengi!
Hey, hey!
Perhaps it would be best
if you left.
My colleague here
takes his duties very seriously.
I promise to tell Odo
you were here.
Let's go, Quark.
So...
that is how the solids
experience intimacy.
Not all solids.
Humans... Bajorans...
I really must thank you, Odo.
For what?
For giving me
new insight into the solids.
And what have you learned?
That what they consider intimacy
is only a shadow
of what we experience
in the Great Link.
You don't agree?
I didn't say that.
You have done this before?
Not often.
But when you have,
you enjoyed it?
Yes.
And you regret
not having experienced it
with Major Kira?
I'd rather not
discuss Major Kira.
I don't see why not.
When we link
your feelings for her
are made very clear.
Then why do you insist
that we talk about it?
Because talking is still
very important to you.
But one day, it won't be.
One day, the Link
will be all that you need
and that day is coming soon.
Is it?
It's amazing
that you have survived
this long without it.
It's only now
after I have been away
from the Great Link myself
that I understand how painful
it must have been for you.
It hasn't always been easy.
Odo, you never have
to be alone again.
Well...
I'd better be going.
There's a meeting
of the station's Ruling Council.
Dukat and Weyoun
are expecting me.
That meeting was held
three days ago.
Three days?
Three days.
How could I have lost track
of that much time?
Does that bother you?
Yes, it does.
Well, don't let it.
You've been living
with the solids' concept of time
for too long.
Let them worry
about their meetings
their schedules,
their obligations.
None of that
has anything to do with you.
You are a changeling.
You are timeless.
As am I.
You asked to see me, Major?
That's right. L...
First, tell me something.
What do you think of this?
It's one of Ziyal's paintings.
I know who the artist is.
Her father gave it to me.
He claims it won some sort
of prize on Cardassia.
Gul Dukat must be very proud...
I suppose.
Is it...
any good?
I think so.
Why, don't you?
I don't know how to judge it.
You see, my people
lack a sense of aesthetics.
That's too bad.
I sometimes think so as well.
But if aesthetics
were truly important
the Founders
would have included it
in our genetic makeup.
Or... they made a mistake.
Gods don't make mistakes.
Though... sometimes...
I think it would be nice
to be able to carry a tune.
So...
what can I do for you, Major?
It's about Rom.
Oh, yes.
The Ferengi saboteur.
He has been in a holding cell
for over a week.
Has it really been that long?
And I was hoping
that you would consider
releasing him.
Impossible.
You can't release a man
and then execute him.
It makes no sense.
Execute Rom?
He committed an act of terrorism
against the Dominion.
Not only did he try to
interfere with our efforts
to take down the minefield
but, as I understand
it, he's also
the diabolical genius
who came up with the idea
of self-replicating mines
in the first place.
I'm afraid there's
no getting around it, Major.
He must be made an example,
so that others think twice
before they act against us.
He is married
to a Bajoran citizen.
I'm well aware of that
and I'm willing to believe...
for now...
his wife is not
a coconspirator.
Otherwise, treaty or no treaty,
she would share
her husband's fate.
I'm sorry, Major.
The Dominion takes a dim view
of terrorism.
Your... friend...
must pay the price
for his crime.
We'll see what
the Bajoran government
has to say about that.
I'm afraid
their pleas
will fall on deaf ears.
Major.
Would this be
more aesthetically pleasing
if it were blue?
I'm going to die.
Stop saying that.
I didn't say it...
he did.
What I said is
they're planning to execute you.
It's not the same thing.
It is to me.
Rom, we are not going
to let them hurt you.
Kira has gone
to the Bajoran Council
of Ministers.
She's asking them
to lodge an official protest.
That's sweet, but I doubt
it'll do any good.
And I've talked
to Grand Nagus Zek himself
and he has offered to buy
your freedom
from the Dominion.
I don't think Weyoun
cares much for latinum.
I'm a dead man.
Will you stop upsetting Leeta?
Sorry.
Besides...
you think your big brother
will let anything
happen to you?
What can you do?
I'm not sure
but I will think of something.
No matter what it takes...
no matter what I have to do
I'm going to get
you out of here.
You do that
and... I'll work
your dabo tables for free.
For how long?
An entire year.
Make it two.
Brother!
Shh!
Isn't your life worth two years?
Now, sit tight
and trust your older brother.
But I don't want you
to try to save me.
What are you talking about?
They must have done something
to his mind.
What mind?
I'm serious.
Brother, you have
more important things
to worry about.
The bar is doing fine,
but thanks for caring.
I'm not talking about the bar.
What could be more important
than your life?
Destroying
the anti-graviton beam.
Shh!
To prevent the Dominion
from taking down the minefield.
You've got to finish
what I started.
The fate of the entire
Alpha Quadrant
rests in your hands.
Billions and billions of people
are counting on you.
Boy, are they going
to be disappointed.
Brother...
you can do this.
You have to do this.
You will do this.
What happens if I get caught?
Then we'll die together...
side by side,
heads held high...
knowing we did our best.
Oh, Rom.
But I don't want to die.
If that's what's written...
then that's what's written.
Now get going, Brother.
You have a lot of work to do.
So... tell me, Leeta,
what else is new?
Have they fixed the sonic shower
in our quarters yet?
Ziyal.
Nerys.
I haven't seen you in weeks.
Do you have a minute?
Sit down.
I need you to talk
to your father for me.
About what?
Rom.
Father?
Ah!
I need to talk to you.
Is something wrong, my dear?
Nothing that you can't fix.
Name it.
I want you to free Rom.
You're joking.
Not at all.
I can't free Rom, Ziyal.
He's been sentenced to death
by the Dominion.
You can pardon him.
Don't you see, Father?
This is your chance
to show the Bajoran people...
to show Major Kira...
who you really are...
a forgiving,
compassionate man.
A great man.
Tell me something, Ziyal...
were you involved
in any way...
with the plans
to sabotage this station?
No, I wasn't involved.
You're sure about that?
I can't help you unless
you tell me the truth.
I am telling you the truth.
The question is: Have you
been telling me the truth?
About what?
That the Bajorans
are wrong about you.
That you regret the horrible
things you had to do
during the occupation.
I do regret them, Ziyal...
deeply.
Then this is your chance
to prove it to everyone
including me.
Show us that you're
capable of mercy.
Rom...
is an enemy of the state
and enemies of the state
do not deserve mercy.
Spoken like a true Cardassian.
I am a Cardassian.
And so are you.
No, I'm not!
I could never be like you.
Ziyal...
You can't trust them.
I trust latinum,
and so do they.
Five bars will buy me
five Nausicaans
and a fast ship
and very few questions.
Breaking Rom out
of the holding cell
will be child's play
compared to the things
they're used to doing.
Forget about it, Quark.
Freeing your brother's
going to take very careful
and precise planning.
It's not the Nausicaan way...
they're thugs.
They'll come strutting
onto the station
look at a Jem'Hadar
the wrong way
and before you know it,
there's blood on the Promenade.
Think I can get my money back?
Major...
a freighter loaded
with Tammeron grain
is due within the hour.
See to it that Cargo Bay 5
is ready to receive it.
I'll take care of it.
I'll have a...
Yes, you will.
Now.
That attitude of yours, Major...
it won't be tolerated forever.
You don't like my attitude,
Damar?
You're welcome
to try to change it.
I don't know what Dukat
sees in that woman.
Then you need to have
your eyes examined.
One kanar.
Want me to leave the bottle?
Maybe I should
have you taste it first.
Make sure it isn't poisoned.
Poisoning the customers
is bad for business.
True.
But some people may place
a brother's revenge
above business.
Not this Ferengi.
You're a credit
to your race, Quark.
Unlike your brother
you've chosen to back
the winning side.
All right, you going to tell me
or do you want me to guess?
Tell you what?
Oh, don't be coy with me.
Either someone
you don't like has died
or your promotion
came through.
It's better than that.
It's about the minefield.
What about it?
It's coming down.
Oh, I've heard that before.
Remember those field tests
I was telling you about?
They were successful.
We've begun to deactivate
the mines.
Well...
you've got your work
cut out for you.
What's it going to take...
a couple months? A year?
One week.
A week?
That's right.
One week...
and the Alpha Quadrant
is ours.
Gentlemen,
this mission cannot succeed
without the involvement of
the Klingon Defense Forces.
We agree with you, Captain.
Chancellor Gowron does not.
Then you will have
to change his mind.
The Chancellor is reluctant
to commit such a large fleet
to a single engagement.
He believes it would leave
the Empire vulnerable.
Starfleet Command had
the same concerns about Earth.
But after careful consideration,
they decided
it was worth the risk.
General, perhaps you should
return to Kronos
and make your plea in person.
The Chancellor has
great respect for you.
If you cannot persuade him,
no one can.
I will go to see Gowron
and you will come with me.
No.
The Chancellor no longer
considers me a friend.
I know.
But what could be better?
An ally and an enemy both
telling him the same thing.
He'll have no other
choice but to agree.
Gentlemen, I need those ships.
And you shall have them.
A week?
Are you sure about that?
That's what he said.
Believe me,
this was no idle boast.
We have to stop them.
And end up in a holding cell
like my brother?
No, thanks.
If we could only get to Odo...
make him see what's going on.
Then maybe he could help us.
Forget about Odo.
First, we can't get to him.
Second, even if we did,
he wouldn't help us.
Then what we have to do
is warn Starfleet.
And how do you suggest
we get a message to them?
You're asking me?
You're the terrorist.
I'm just a bartender.
There you are.
From the look on your faces
I can see you haven't
had much luck
getting Rom out of jail.
And the news just keeps
getting worse.
It's not all bad.
Trust us, Jake.
It is.
Not for me.
I'm getting a message
out to my dad.
How?
I'm a reporter...
I have my ways.
Come on, Jake,
this is no time for games.
- Morn?
- He's going home
for his mother's birthday
or something.
He has an encrypted message
for my dad
in one of her presents.
Are you sure this is reliable?
I've known the courier
for five years.
I trust him.
Then we have a problem.
According to this
the minefield's coming
down in three days.
The Ninth Fleet won't be
here for at least four.
Then I suggest
we go without them.
What about the Klingons?
Looks like we go
without them, too.
We've run out of time, Admiral.
If those Dominion reinforcements
come through the wormhole
we'll have lost everything.
Then we take the ships we have,
fight our way to Deep Space 9
and destroy
the anti-graviton emitter.
It's our only hope.
Do it.
There.
Where?
Over there.
That flash of light
was the anti-graviton beam
hitting a mine.
And disabling
its replication unit.
Exactly.
Didn't you see it?
I'm afraid not.
For months,
you've been demanding
that I take down those mines
and now that it's
finally happening
you can't even see it.
Weak eyes.
Excuse me?
My people have poor eyesight.
It's something we've learned
to live with.
Jem'Hadar
on the other hand...
excellent vision.
I suppose they need it
more than we do.
Ah! There's another one.
I'll have
to take your word for it.
Once we disable the replication
units in all the mines
we can detonate
the entire minefield.
And I guarantee you...
weak eyes or not...
that explosion you will see.
When will you be ready
to proceed?
Approximately 78 hours.
Three more days
and we can start to bring
the Jem'Hadar reinforcements
through the wormhole.
Excellent! I knew you
could do it, Dukat.
Did you?
I never doubted you
for a moment.
Sir.
I have new information
on enemy fleet movements.
Go ahead.
The Second Fleet has fallen back
past the Kotanka system
while the Fifth Fleet
has pulled out of the fighting
along the Vulcan border.
Both fleets have converged
here... Starbase 375.
Isn't that where Captain Sisko
is stationed?
He's been made an adjutant
- to Admiral Ross.
- Good for him.
Now, why have those fleets
gathered there?
I'm not sure.
You're not sure?
Two large enemy fleets
break off from the front lines
and rendezvous at a starbase
and you have no idea why?
Well, we'll just have
to find out, won't we?
See that you do.
He should speak to you
with greater respect.
Someday, I'll let you
teach him that lesson
but right now,
there's something
more pressing
I need you to do.
It's of a personal nature,
a matter of some... delicacy.
It's about my daughter.
Ziyal?
We've had a misunderstanding.
I want you to go
and convince her to...
speak with me.
Sir, I really feel
I would be more valuable
tracking the enemy fleet.
I've given you an order, Damar.
We're on the verge
of a great victory
and when it comes,
I want my daughter at my side.
Is that understood?
I really believed
my father had changed.
That he wanted
to be a man of peace.
I think he believes that, too...
when it suits his purpose.
Everything he's ever said
to me has been a lie.
Not everything.
He really does care about you.
I don't care.
I am not going back to him.
You don't believe me, do you?
Right now, you're angry and hurt
but that's going to pass
and then you'll have
to decide what to do.
Ziyal!
I need to speak to you.
You and I have nothing
to talk about.
Maybe not,
but you and your father do.
He wants to see you.
Well, I don't want to see him.
You heard her.
Stay out of this, Major.
Ziyal, listen.
Your father is a great man...
a man of destiny...
but he also carries
great burdens.
He knows our alliance
with the Dominion
is a dangerous one.
If we show any sign of weakness,
our allies will turn on us.
That is why we must all
help him remain strong.
So I ask you to be
a true daughter of Cardassia
and stand beside him.
It should be obvious,
even to you, Damar
that I am not "a true
daughter of Cardassia"!
What is obvious to me
is that your father
should have left you to rot
in that Breen prison camp.
But he didn't.
He took pity on you
and it's your duty to repay him.
Now come with me.
Let her go.
And if I don't?
What happens, then?
I was hoping you'd ask.
Did you kill him?
No, but I thought about it.
What are you going to do
when he wakes up?
That's up to him.
I just came to wish you luck.
Oh, thank you.
My father says
you can never have
too much good luck.
Your father sounds
like a wise man.
And he makes a fierce jambalaya.
What's this?
Ancient Bajoran texts.
Ah. The Emissary
looks for guidance
on the eve of battle.
Guidance, insights, loopholes...
I'll take anything I can get.
And what do
the Prophets tell you?
That I have a long way to go
before I can make any sense
of their prophecies.
Maybe when this war is over,
you can look at them closer.
That would be a change.
Spend a week or two
down on Bajor.
Visit the Dakeen Monastery.
I've never been on Bajor.
I hear it's quite nice.
Nice?
That hardly describes it at all.
There are parts
of the Eastern Province
that are like Eden itself...
lush green valleys
covered in wildflowers
that seem to spring
up overnight;
hundreds of small,
crystal-clear ponds
interconnected by waterfalls...
All right, all right.
I'm convinced.
I'm already planning
my next R&R down there.
You know, it sounds like,
when your assignment
on Deep Space 9 is over
and Bajor is welcomed
into the Federation
you're going to have
a tough time saying good-bye.
I don't plan to say good-bye.
I plan to build
a house on Bajor.
And what if Starfleet
assigns you
to a different sector?
I will go wherever they send me
but when I go home...
it will be to Bajor.
Chief! I was
just coming to see you.
Can you believe it?
They made me an Ensign.
I hadn't realized things
were going so bad.
Scary, isn't it?
If my classmates
at the Academy
could only see me now.
They'd be surprised,
would they?
"Amazed" is more like it.
What do they know?
Anyway, I just want to say
thanks for all your help.
My help?
I've learned a lot from you
and not just about engineering.
You've shown me what it takes
to be a good soldier.
Don't let that uniform
go to your head.
You've a lot to learn yet...
and you will.
Congratulations, Ensign.
Wear it with pride.
I intend to, Chief.
Captain on the Bridge.
I've kept it warm for you, Ben.
Ensign, alert all ships.
We're moving out.
Aye, sir.
Our initial
intelligence reports
have been verified.
The Federation fleet
is on the move.
Do we know their destination?
Yes. It appears
they're headed here.
Here?
Oh, ho, ho, ho.
He knows we're taking down
the minefield.
Someone must've gotten
a message out.
So it would seem.
No matter.
We'll crush them.
Yes. Yes, we will
but in order to do that,
I'm going to have to pull
a significant number
of our ships
off the front lines.
Do it.
Come in.
Once the minefield is down
we'll have more
than enough ships
to take their place.
I understand.
One moment, please.
I want your permission
to arrest Major Kira.
Kira? What about Ziyal?
Did you talk to her?
She doesn't want to see you.
When I insisted,
the Major... objected.
What did you do to Ziyal?
I did nothing to her.
Then why did the Major
attack you?
You must have done something...
threatened my daughter
in some way.
Damar, I told you to be tactful.
Excuse me.
Don't you think
resolving family squabbles
can wait
until after we've won this war?
Weak eyes, good ears.
Yes, of course.
You're quite right.
Then you're clear
on what must be done?
I'm going to call back
enough ships to destroy
the Federation fleet
and hold this station.
The Federation is
moving against us?
That's right.
Now, I want to know
exactly what went on
between you and Ziyal.
It's odd.
I've stood here countless times
and yet, somehow it
all looks different.
It's the solids.
They look small, don't they?
Insignificant.
It's not their fault.
I'm not placing blame.
They're trapped.
Confined to a single shape.
A single perspective.
It's so limiting.
I feel sorry for them.
They need our guidance, Odo
not our pity.
They cherish their freedom.
We'll have to break them
of that.
Break them?
In a manner of speaking.
Oh, this language
of the solids...
it's so imprecise.
What exactly do you plan to do?
The solids are no longer
your concern, Odo.
What must be done will be done.
It's as simple as that.
Forgive me for intruding
but I have important news
about the war.
Why don't you return
to your quarters, Odo?
I'll join you there shortly.
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
I promise.
I must say...
you're doing a
wonderful job with Odo.
Meaning what?
Meaning that he's always posed
a potential threat to our plans
but you seem to have...
neutralized him quite nicely.
Neutralize Odo?
Is that why you think I'm here?
Odo is a changeling.
Bringing him home,
returning him to the Great Link
means more to us
than the Alpha Quadrant itself.
Is that clear?
I meant no disrespect.
Well, of course you didn't.
You are what you are...
a loyal subject of the Dominion.
Come. Walk with me.
You said you had important news.
Major!
Kira!
Kira, wait, please.
I have nothing to say to you.
I understand that you're angry.
Oh, you bet I am angry.
Do you have any idea
what's going on?
Yes... somewhat.
I've been occupied.
Ah... Dukat is bringing
down the minefield
the Federation is
about to be overrun
by the Dominion reinforcements
and Weyoun has ordered
Rom's execution
and you have been occupied.
This is so difficult
to explain.
If you're going to talk to me
about the Link, don't bother.
I'm a solid, remember?
I won't understand.
Nerys...
I'm sorry.
Sorry?
That's what you wanted
to tell me?
You're sorry?
Yes.
Well, let me
tell you something, Odo.
We are way, way past "sorry."
Sir, incoming message
from the Cortéz.
They're still having
trouble stabilizing
the guidance thrusters
on the port nacelle.
Tell them to drop back
and make repairs.
Bring up the Sarek
to take its place.
Will do.
That's the 11th ship
to fall out of formation.
Nice of you to keep track,
Garak.
He can't help being negative.
It's in his nature.
On the contrary.
I always hope for the best.
Experience, unfortunately
has taught me
to expect the worst.
I'm picking something up.
It's a large Dominion fleet,
bearing 004 mark 009.
How large?
1,254 ships.
They outnumber us two to one.
Now who's being negative?
Ensign, on screen.
Maximum magnification.
Aye, sir.
To all ships...
this is Captain Sisko.
Assume attack formation
delta-two.
There's an old saying...
"Fortune favors the bold."
Well...
I guess we're about to find out.