Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
The Dominion won't attack Earth.
How can you be sure?
Because Earth isn't the key
to the Alpha Quadrant...
the wormhole is.
And whoever controls
Deep Space 9
controls the wormhole.
Target locked.
Fire!
Execute Rom?
He committed an act of terrorism
against the Dominion.
You've got to finish
what I started.
The fate
of the entire Alpha Quadrant
rests in your hands.
What happens if I get caught?
If those Dominion reinforcements
come through the wormhole
we'll have lost everything.
Then we take the ships we have,
fight our way to Deep Space 9
and destroy
the anti-graviton emitter.
It's our only hope.
Dukat is bringing
down the minefield
the Federation is
about to be overrun
by the Dominion reinforcements
and Weyoun has ordered
Rom's execution.
I'm sorry.
We are way, way past "sorry."
It's a large Dominion fleet.
1,254 ships.
They outnumber us two to one.
There's an old saying...
"Fortune favors the bold."
Well...
I guess we're about to find out.
And now the conclusion.
Sisko to all ships.
Cruiser and galaxy wings,
drop to half impulse.
You, too, Commander.
Half impulse.
I feel sorry for the Klingons.
They're going to miss
a very interesting fight.
I have a feeling
we're going to miss them.
Forget the Klingons.
Our job is to get
to Deep Space 9
and prevent
the Dominion reinforcements
from coming through
the wormhole.
And that's
what we're going to do.
Attack-fighters,
tactical pattern theta.
Concentrate your fire
on the Cardassian ships
and then split off
into squadrons
and run like hell.
Why is he only targeting
the Cardassian ships?
He's hoping to get them
to break formation
so they'll go after
the Federation fighters.
He knows the Jem'Hadar
will stand their ground,
but the Cardassians
might just get angry enough
to take the bait.
Which would open a hole
we can punch through.
You're getting
quite an education.
Attack-fighters
in theta formation.
Cruiser and galaxy wings
at half impulse.
Sisko to attack-fighters.
Prepare to engage on my command.
Aye, sir.
"Cannon to the right of them
"Cannon to the left of them
"Cannon in front of them
Volley'd and thunder'd..."
"Storm'd at with shot and shell
"Boldly they rode and well
"Into the jaws of Death,
Into the mouth of Hell
Rode the six hundred."
Whatever it is
you two are reciting
I wish you'd stop.
Steady, Ensign.
It's just a poem.
It's not the poem
that's bothering me.
Stop worrying about those ships.
Focus on your work.
That's what I do.
You should listen to him,
Ensign.
He's a professional.
Attack-fighters, full impulse.
Fire at will.
They're not taking the bait.
Ensign, send in the second wave.
Tell them to keep targeting
the Cardassians.
Aye, sir.
Second wave on its way.
Third and fourth wave
on hot standby.
Mr. O'Brien, have
destroyer units 2 and 6
move in closer.
They need more cover fire.
And tell Captains
Diego and Reynolds
to stay alert.
They may try to outflank us.
It's a very clever strategy.
But then I'd expect nothing less
from Captain Sisko.
The Captain is
a very clever man.
You do see it, don't you?
Of course I do.
Well, then, perhaps you'd like
to explain
Captain Sisko's strategy
to the Founder yourself.
I could never hope
to match your eloquence.
True.
Sisko is trying to provoke us
into opening a hole
in our lines.
He's determined to get here
and stop us from taking
down this minefield.
Now, I plan...
to give Sisko his opening...
and then...
close it on him.
What about the minefield?
Are we still on schedule?
We should be able
to detonate the mines
in eight hours.
Good.
Eight hours.
I'll hold you to that, Dukat.
I'd like to toss
that smug little Vorta
out the nearest airlock.
And his Founder with him.
Now, now, Damar
that's no way to talk
about our valued allies...
not until this war
is over anyway.
Sir, there is one other thing.
Make it brief.
I'm concerned
about further attempts
to sabotage this station.
The enemy knows
if they don't act soon
it'll be too late.
By "enemy," I assume
you're referring
to Rom's associates.
I doubt whether
he was working alone
when he tried
to sabotage this station.
He must've had help.
His wife Leeta...
Jake Sisko...
Major Kira.
What are you proposing?
That we arrest them
and keep them in custody
at least until the wormhole
is reopened.
It's a wise precaution.
But our Bajoran allies
might object
to an arrest without cause.
If anyone asks
we are merely holding them
for questioning, hmm?
And, Damar
make sure they're
not harmed in any way.
Major Kira is important
to my daughter.
And to me.
Sir, about your daughter...
perhaps it would be better,
for her own sake
if Ziyal were confined
to quarters.
For what reason?
To be perfectly honest, sir
I don't completely trust her.
And neither should you.
Are you accusing my daughter
of being a saboteur?
I'm not accusing her
of anything.
But she is... quite friendly
with Major Kira.
That will be all, Damar.
She doesn't appreciate
what it means to be Cardassian
or to be your daughter.
But she is my daughter.
That may mean nothing to you
but it means everything to me.
I heard the Federation
fleet has been ambushed.
I heard two Cardassian soldiers
saying the fleet was
completely destroyed.
Don't believe
everything you hear.
Jake's right.
Sisko will get here.
The question is:
Will he get here soon enough?
He's only got seven hours
before they detonate
the minefield
and start bringing
the reinforcements
through the wormhole.
We've got to stop them.
How?
What if we cut off
the power supply
to the main computer?
Shut down the whole station.
Oh, great.
That would put me out
of business altogether.
Well, it would also keep them
from detonating the mines.
Okay...
so we shut down
the main computer.
How?
A bomb.
A bomb?!
What kind of bomb?
Leave that to me.
It'll be crude, but effective.
The main computer
is in the Central Core.
It's too heavily guarded.
You'll never be able
to smuggle a bomb into there.
I'll plant the bomb.
All we need to do is
distract the guards.
In here.
Secure the door.
Ah, Major, there you are.
How nice of you
to gather your friends for us.
I'm off duty, Damar.
What do you want?
I want you to come with us,
all three of you.
Where?
To the Security Office.
We have to ask you
a few questions.
What kind of questions?
You'll find out
when we get there.
Go ahead, Major, try something.
Nothing would make me happier.
Don't worry.
It'll be all right.
Of course it will.
You've nothing to hide, do you?
You certainly don't.
I'll say this for Captain Sisko,
he is persistent.
That's the ninth wave
of Federation fighters
he's sent against us.
Well, his persistence
is about to pay off.
Let's give him
his reward, shall we?
Have a half dozen
squadrons break formation
and go after those fighters.
Yes, sir.
Two squadrons
of Cardassian attack ships
are breaking formation.
They're going
after our fighters.
They're taking the bait.
We've opened a hole
in their lines.
Have we?
Sir, do you see
those Galore-class destroyers?
I see them.
It's a trap.
It is also an opportunity
and we may not get
another one.
Ensign, have Galaxy Wings 9-1
and 9-3 engage those destroyers.
All other ships,
head for that opening.
Anyone who gets through
doesn't stop
until they reach Deep Space 9.
Congratulations, Captain!
You wanted them angry,
they're angry.
The Magellan and the Venture
are supposed to be protecting
our starboard flanks.
They're in too tight.
Ensign, tell fighter
squadrons 6, 7 and 8 to...
Sir, I can't
get through to anybody.
Communications are down.
They're jamming our signal
by generating
a rotating EM pulse.
Can you clear it?
I'm trying.
War is such... thirsty work.
Don't you agree?
Perhaps if you didn't
talk so much
your throat wouldn't get so dry.
Cardassians do like to talk.
I suppose it can be
a failing at times.
No.
To the conquerors
of the Federation.
Aren't you being
a bit premature?
I don't think so.
Not with 2800 Dominion ships
waiting to come
through that wormhole.
Well, those ships
aren't going to be here
for another five hours,
and need I remind you
a lot can happen
in that amount of time.
Oh!
Tell me, Weyoun...
have you ever been diagnosed
as anhedonic?
You think I'm incapable
of experiencing joy
just because I'm cautious?
We didn't defeat the Federation
by being cautious.
We haven't defeated it yet
and even if we do,
it's only the beginning.
Holding onto a prize
as vast as the Federation
isn't going to be easy.
It's going to require
an enormous number of ships
a massive occupation army...
and constant vigilance.
I look forward to it.
I'm sure you also looked forward
to occupying Bajor
and we all know what
a disappointment that was.
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
On Bajor,
I merely implemented policy.
I didn't make it.
If I had, things would have
turned out quite differently.
If you ask me
the key to holding
the Federation...
is Earth.
If there's going to be
an organized
resistance against us
its birthplace will be there.
You could be right.
Then our first step
is to eradicate its population.
It's the only way.
You can't do that.
Why not?
Because!
A true victory
is to make your enemy see
they were wrong to oppose you
in the first place.
To force them...
to acknowledge your greatness.
Then you kill them?
Only if it's necessary.
I had no idea.
Perhaps the biggest
disappointment in my life
is that the Bajoran people
still refuse to appreciate
how lucky they were
to have me as their liberator.
I protected them
in so many ways...
cared for them
as if they were my own children
but to this day
is there a single...
statue of me on Bajor?
I would guess not.
And you'd be right.
Take Captain Sisko...
an otherwise intelligent,
perceptive man, hmm?
Even he refuses to grant me
the respect I deserve.
You find that amusing?
Not at all.
I find it...
...fascinating.
Laugh all you want.
History will prove me right.
I have news, Odo.
Our battle with the Federation
fleet is going well.
There are people
out there fighting...
dying...
people who used
to be my friends.
They're solids, Odo.
You must remember that.
I know, but they still
mean something to me.
The Link means more.
That's what I keep
telling myself
but somehow I can't
quite believe it.
You asked me for clarity, Odo.
I gave it to you.
Now you must accept it.
It's Major Kira, isn't it?
You still have
strong feelings for her.
She doesn't deserve
your loyalty, Odo.
You cannot allow a solid
to deny you
your rightful place
in the Great Link.
I couldn't permit it.
What are you saying?
The Major has been arrested.
On what charge?
That hardly matters.
What matters is
she will be found guilty
and sentenced to death.
No.
Her death is your salvation.
Link with me, Odo.
Embrace the clarity.
It is the only thing
that will give you peace.
No.
You cannot help her, Odo.
You cannot help
any of the solids
no matter how much
you may want to.
It's too late for them.
Sir, we've just lost
the Sitak and the Majestic.
We're on our own.
Com's back on line!
Four enemy ships directly ahead!
Evasive maneuvers...
pattern omega.
We're going through!
That's one down.
Can we shake the other three?
I'm trying.
We've lost aft shields.
Forward shields
are down to 15 percent.
Wouldn't this be
a good time to cloak?
The cloaking system's fried.
Auxiliary power to weapons.
We're going to fight
our way out of this.
It's the Klingons, sir.
They're here.
We're being hailed
by Commander Worf.
On screen.
Captain,
I'm sorry we were late.
It was not easy
to convince Chancellor Gowron
to spare us any ships.
I'm just glad you could
join us, Commander.
Captain, the Klingons
have broken a hole
in the Dominion lines.
Dax, can you get us through?
I'd love to try.
Any other ships make it?
No, sir.
We only have three hours
before the minefields
are detonated.
Set a course for Deep Space 9.
Maximum warp.
The Defiant has broken through
all our lines.
It's on its way here.
Shall I order a pursuit?
At once.
The Defiant is no match
for this station.
If Sisko wants to commit suicide
I say we let him.
Don't scream.
I won't hurt you.
I just have one question.
What's that?
Do you know how to make
hasperat soufflé?
Lunch for Major Kira.
Major Kira
has already been fed.
And I can only imagine
the slop you served her.
What I have here
is hasperat soufflé
just the way
the Major likes it.
This is a jail, not a hotel.
The Major will eat
what the other prisoners eat.
Do you know who I am?
Gul Dukat's daughter.
That's right.
Now, I suggest you allow
us to deliver this food.
I can't do that.
However...
I will take the tray to her.
After I examine it.
Um... is that really necessary?
Lift the lid.
If you insist.
You see?
Hasperat soufflé.
Just as I said.
Stop poking it.
It's very delicate.
Now you've ruined it.
How much longer before they
detonate the minefield?
I wish you'd stop asking that.
Sorry.
I'd say about 90 minutes.
My time grows short.
Don't say that.
The only reason
they haven't killed me yet
is that I'm part
of their victory celebration.
7:00: Dukat makes a speech.
8:30: Cake and raktajino.
8:45: Execute the Ferengi.
All right...
no one move!
Brother!
I knew you would come.
It's a surprise to me.
Now, just keep calm and stay
where you are.
Understand?
Don't move.
You...
open the holding cells.
I said
You just told them
not to move.
Right.
Nobody moves... except you.
Now...
open the cells.
Quark?
Yes?
Take down the force fields.
Force fields...
I'd kiss you, Quark,
but there isn't time.
We have to find a way
to shut down
the power to the main computer.
I can do that.
Oh, Rom.
That is, if we can make it
to the Central Computer
Core without being killed.
Right.
Rom, you're with me.
The rest of you
find someplace to stay
out of sight.
Will do.
I know you're confused, Odo
but you don't have to be.
All the answers you
seek are in the Link.
Come in.
Forgive the intrusion
but Major Kira,
the Ferengi saboteur
and the rest of their
terrorist group have escaped
from the holding cells.
For your own protection
I must ask you to come with me.
I want them caught.
They will be.
But in the meantime,
you'll both be safer in Ops.
Very well.
Odo?
I'll be fine here.
You're sure?
Yes.
Get out of here!
Do you hear that?
That's Bajoran phaser fire.
Why would Dominion troops
be using Bajoran weapons?
Never underestimate
the element of surprise.
You have less than 40 minutes
to shut down the main computer.
I hope that's enough time.
It'll have to be.
Can you keep the Dominion
patrols off our backs?
I'll head down to Security.
Create enough false alarms
to keep them occupied.
Any questions?
I could ask why?
I don't think there's time
to explain it.
Besides, I think
you know the answer.
What about the Link?
The Link... was paradise.
But it appears
I'm not ready for paradise.
Good luck.
You, too.
Dax, what's our ETA?
11 minutes.
That's cutting it close.
How's it going, Rom?
I wish you'd stop asking that.
Sorry, sorry.
I'm not going to make it.
All right, then concentrate
on cutting off the power
to the station's weapons array.
Without weapons
they won't be able
to detonate the minefield.
Not for a while anyway.
Sir, the Klingons
have outflanked us.
Our lines are
beginning to crumble.
There's nothing to worry about.
In exactly four minutes
thousands of Dominion ships
will come pouring
through that wormhole.
I just hope the Defiant
gets here in time
for Sisko to see it.
Ben, if I were you
I'd start coming up
with a Plan "B."
Almost there.
I just need to decouple
the ODN relays.
The last mines have
been neutralized.
We're ready to detonate
the minefield, sir.
Fire!
Done.
Uh-oh.
What is it?
We were too late.
What do we do now, Captain?
Take us into the wormhole.
What the hell.
We're only going to meet
a couple of thousand
Dominion ships.
One ship
against an entire fleet?
That's a hell of a Plan "B."
Chief,
how does that poem end?
You don't want to know.
Send a message
to our listening posts
in the Gamma Quadrant.
Tell the reinforcements
that the Alpha Quadrant
awaits them.
Sir...
the Defiant...
it's heading for the wormhole.
Destroy it.
What's wrong, Damar?
Our weapons...
they're off-line.
They've been sabotaged.
How can that be?
Major Kira.
Full stop.
Chief, divert all power
to forward shields and weapons.
Captain, I'm reading
multiple warp signatures ahead.
On screen.
Maximum magnification.
Lock phasers.
Prepare to launch
quantum torpedoes.
Why have you brought me here?
Show yourselves.
What do you want?
The Sisko has returned to us.
He arrives with questions.
There are always questions.
I didn't ask to come here.
You desire to end the game.
What game?
I don't understand.
You seek to shed
your corporeal existence.
That cannot be allowed.
The game must not end.
The game.
You mean my life.
Is that what this is about?
You don't want me to die?
The game must continue.
You are the Sisko.
Believe me, I don't want to die,
but I have to do
everything I can
to prevent the Dominion
from conquering
the Alpha Quadrant.
If that means sacrificing
my life and the life of my crew
so be it.
We do not agree.
We find your reasoning flawed.
Insufficient.
I'm flattered you feel that way,
but it doesn't change anything.
Now, send me back to my ship.
This isn't what I meant.
I want to return to my reality.
You are the Sisko.
I am also a Starfleet Captain.
I have a job to do
and I intend to do it.
The Sisko is belligerent.
Aggressive.
Adversarial.
You're damn right
I'm adversarial.
You have no right
to interfere with my life.
We have every right.
Fine.
You want to interfere?
Then interfere.
Do something about
those Dominion reinforcements.
That is a corporeal matter.
Corporeal matters
do not concern us.
The hell they don't.
What about Bajor?
You can't tell me
Bajor doesn't concern you.
You've sent the Bajorans
Orbs and Emissaries.
You've even encouraged them
to create
an entire religion around you.
You even told me once
that you were of Bajor.
So don't you tell me
you're not concerned
with corporeal matters.
I don't want
to see Bajor destroyed.
Neither do you, but we all know
that's exactly
what's going to happen
if the Dominion takes over
the Alpha Quadrant.
You say you don't want me
to sacrifice my life.
Well, fine.
Neither do I.
You want to be Gods.
Then be Gods.
I need a miracle.
Bajor needs a miracle.
Stop those ships!
We are of Bajor.
But what of the Sisko?
He is intrusive.
He tries to control the game.
A penance must be exacted.
It is agreed.
The Sisko is of Bajor,
but he will find no rest there.
His pagh will follow
another path.
What path is that?
Phaser banks fully charged.
Forward shields at 100 percent.
Torpedoes ready.
Targets locked.
Here they come.
Fire on my command.
There must be thousands of them.
And half of them
have locked targets on us.
Steady, people.
Make every shot count.
Benjamin.
They've cloaked.
I'm not picking up
any neutrino emissions.
Then... where did they go?
Wherever they went...
I don't think
they're coming back.
Sir, the wormhole is opening.
The Defiant.
Our reinforcements
must be right behind.
No, sir.
There's no sign of them.
That's impossible.
Check our listening posts
in the Gamma Quadrant.
They're not there, either.
But they entered the wormhole.
Where are they?!
I don't know.
The Defiant has opened fire
on us!
Obviously.
Can you get our weapons
back on line?
Not for a while.
Sir, 200 enemy ships
have broken through our lines.
They're headed this way.
Time to start packing.
Contact our forces
in the Alpha Quadrant.
Tell them to fall back
to the Cardassian territory.
It appears this war
is going to take
longer than expected.
We'll meet you at Airlock Five.
Sir?
Victory was within our grasp.
We have to evacuate
the station, sir!
Bajor...
the Federation...
the Alpha Quadrant...
all lost.
We have to go now, sir.
Go?
The Federation ships...
they'll be here soon.
We have to get back
to Cardassia.
I have to find my daughter.
I'll send someone for her!
That won't be necessary.
You're wasting your time!
Promenade!
She won't go with you!
Sir, the Dominion forces
are leaving the station.
Let them go.
We're in no shape to stop them.
Captain, we're getting
a message from the Cortéz.
The Dominion fleet
have broken off the fight.
They're in retreat.
Tell the Cortéz
and the rest of the fleet
to rendezvous at Deep Space 9.
All Dominion personnel
proceed to Airlocks 4, 7 and 12
for evacuation.
This is a first priority order.
Repeat, all Dominion personnel
proceed to Airlocks 4, 7 and 12
for evacuation.
Out of the way, out of the way.
Step aside.
Make way for the Founder.
What about Odo?
Is he coming with us?
No.
But he will join us one day.
It's only a matter of time.
Father!
Ah, Ziyal.
I've been looking for you.
I heard about the evacuation.
You're all I have...
all I care about.
No matter how much
I try to hate you
I can't.
I couldn't live with myself
if you hated me.
Come.
We'll talk on the way home.
Home?
Cardassia.
We have to leave here, Ziyal
before the Federation arrives.
I'm not leaving.
These people are our enemies.
They're not my enemies.
I'm one of them.
That's not true.
Father...
I helped Major Kira
and the others escape
from the holding cells.
Do you know what you're saying?
Yes, I do.
I belong here.
Good-bye, Father.
I love you.
No!
You heard her.
She's a traitor.
Ziyal, it's all right.
It's, it's all right.
It's all right.
Ziyal, I forgive you.
We're out of time, sir.
The last ship is waiting for us!
Ziyal, please hear me.
I love you.
I love you, Ziyal.
No. No!
Ziyal...
Ah, Jake.
Welcome back, Captain.
Good to see you, Constable.
It's good to see you all.
Captain...
it would appear
I owe you a barrel of bloodwine.
We'll drink it together.
Worf.
Jadzia.
I guess the wedding's still on.
Quark...
are the holosuites
still working?
Ready and waiting, Chief.
Julian, did you hear that?
The Battle of Britain...
I'll meet you there in an hour.
You've been promoted?
I'm an engineer.
We'll be working together.
Actually,
you'll be working for me.
Really missed you.
It's good to have you back, Dad.
So...
where's Major Kira?
She's in the Infirmary...
with Ziyal.
She loved you.
I could never figure out why.
I guess I never will.
We'll go back to Cardassia,
Ziyal.
We'll be safe there.
You'll live with me...
Maybe Dr. Bashir
can do something for him.
We'll both be
very happy together.
I know you forgive me.
After all, I am your father.
And I forgive you...
my precious girl.
Easy.
Easy now.
I forgive you, too.