SISKO:
Captain's Personal Log,
Stardate 51247.5.
It's been a week since
our return to Deep Space 9,
but the mood
of celebration continues.
We're still at war,
and the station's
been designated headquarters
for the Ninth Fleet.
That, plus
our strategic position
guarding the wormhole,
makes DS9
one of the most
tempting targets
in the entire quadrant.
But for now, at least,
the war seems very far away.
Morning.
Good morning.
Morning, Major.
Good morning, Captain.
Do you know
how much I missed
hearing you say that?
Do you know how much
I hated saying
"Good morning, Dukat"?
I can imagine.
What's on the agenda?
Uh, USS Potemkin
has completed her repairs
and is rejoining the fleet
later today.
Exeter, Sutherland
and Agaki
have submitted
resupply requests
and there are
about 1,000 messages
from Starfleet Command
awaiting your "eyes-only"
attention.
Anything else?
General Martok is waiting
in your office.
Oh, I'll start
with the General.
I thought you would.
Have I mentioned
that it's good to be home?
Once or twice.
All right.
You knew about this,
didn't you?
Oh, I had a pretty good idea.
And you did nothing to stop it.
No.
In fact, I recommended you
for the position myself.
Allow me to offer
my congratulations
to the new
Supreme Commander
of the Ninth Fleet.
Do you have any idea
how much paperwork
a Supreme Commander
has to do?
You're welcome.
( growls )
May I arrange quarters
for you on the station?
No, I'll keep my flag
aboard the Rotarran.
It may be cramped
but at least I'll feel
like I'm still in the war.
By the way, I'd like Worf
to continue functioning
as my principal
Intelligence Officer.
I don't see any problem
with that.
He's the only officer I know
who can never get enough work.
( cackles )
Well, at least if he's busy
he'll stop going on
about this wedding of his.
Oh, there were times
aboard the Rotarran
he nearly drove me mad.
Until his son arrived,
it was all he could talk about.
Then Alexander became
all he could talk about.
The man is nothing
if not single-minded.
I haven't met Worf's son yet.
What's he like?
He's a fine boy...
dedicated, eager.
He has the heart
of his father
but he's not the best
soldier I've ever seen.
But when he ordered me
to bring the system
back online,
I thought he was still talking
about the hydro-static
system, so...
You didn't
engage the pumps
while the check valves
were open.
He did.
I flooded
the entire deck
with super-heated
hydraulic fluid.
It took me three days
to clean it up
but, I swear, it still smells
like burnt dog hair in there.
Oh! Remind me to keep you away
from the Defiant.
You're a menace.
The Rotarran's crew
actually thinks of me
as a good luck charm.
You know, the more mistakes
I make, the safer they feel.
I hope the Ya'Vang's crew
feels the same way.
The Ya'Vang?
I got new orders this morning.
The battle cruiser Ya'Vang
took heavy losses
in their last engagement
so most of the Rotarran's crew
are being transferred there
at the end of the week,
including me.
Uh, more bloodwine?
Why not?
No. Not for me.
Handsome young man.
He must get his
looks from his
mother's side.
What do you want?
Have you had a chance
to reconsider my offer?
We are not getting
married in this bar.
The ceremony
will take place
on the Klingon homeworld
after the war.
Worf, let's do it here,
this week
before Alexander leaves.
QUARK:
Perfect.
I'll handle
all the arrangements.
Wait. I thought
we had agreed.
We did, but I would hate
for Alexander
to miss
his father's wedding.
It would mean so much to him.
And besides,
it may be a long time
before you see him again.
What's going on?
Our wedding plans
have changed.
We are getting
married here
on Deep Space 9
and I would like you
to be my Tawi'Yan.
"Sword-bearer."
It's sort of like
a best man.
Me?
Really?
Oh, that's great!
( yelping )
I'll put that
on your tab.
DAX:
It doesn't
leave much time
to make
all the arrangements
but fortunately, there isn't
that much left to do.
Worf's been planning
the ceremony
for the last three months.
He has everything
figured out
right down
to the color of my shoes.
No offense, Jadzia,
but it seems like this
wedding's
all about what Worf wants.
Uh, Habitat Ring,
Section 51 Gamma.
What about you?
A traditional Klingon wedding
with all the trimmings
is something Worf's
been thinking about
since he was a boy.
It probably has something
to do with being raised
by human parents.
In any case, when it comes
to Klingon tradition,
Worf is very sentimental.
Worf?
All men are sentimental.
They just cover it up with
scowls and clenched jaws.
There are times when Worf
literally gets misty-eyed
talking about
Klingon rituals.
So, uh, that's
why you're letting him
make the plans
for the wedding?
Mostly, but
the truth is
I've already
been through five
Trill ceremonies--
three as a bride,
two as a groom,
and I'm a little bored with it.
Is it my imagination
or did Odo just
try and avoid us?
I didn't notice.
( sighs )
We've been avoiding
each other
ever since the Dominion
left the station.
I think we're both
afraid of talking
about what happened
during the occupation.
What do you mean?
Oh, to tell you the truth,
it's nothing I want to talk
about right now either.
Thank you for coming.
As you probably know by now,
Jadzia and I will be married
here on the station
in six days.
There's nothing
more romantic
than a wedding on
DS9 in springtime.
When the neutrinos
are in bloom.
By tradition,
the Klingon man spends
the four nights
before his wedding
on a mental
and spiritual journey.
It is called Kal'Hyah,
"The Path of Clarity"
and he is accompanied
by his closest male friends.
You cannot imagine
the experience that awaits us--
four long nights filled
with song and fellowship.
A time of unbridled pleasures.
Are we talking
about a bachelor party here?
It is a similar ritual.
Sounds good to me.
Me, too.
Count me in.
We will meet
in the holosuite
tomorrow night
at 2100 hours.
MARTOK:
I advise you all
to get plenty of rest.
Four nights
at a Klingon bachelor party.
Just think of
the possibilities.
Thank God
Keiko's not here.
I wonder what Dax
will be doing
while we're traveling
down Kal'Hyah.
She will be taking
a different journey...
with my wife.
Your wife?
By marrying Worf,
Dax will be joining
the House of Martok.
Since the mistress
of a great House
must approve all marriages,
Sirella will spend
the next four days
evaluating Jadzia.
My lady.
You've put on weight...
and your hair is going gray.
My deterioration
is proceeding apace.
I thought you would be
in your grave by now.
( chuckling )
I shall endeavor to die--
this year, if possible.
Allow me to present
Captain Benjamin Sisko,
Commander of Deep Space 9.
Captain, may I present
the mistress of the House
of Martok, my wife
and the mother
of my children...
Sirella, daughter of Linkasa.
Welcome to
Deep Space 9.
Thank you, Captain.
Where is she?
Jadzia's quarters
are in the Habitat Ring,
Section... 25 Alpha.
Shall I escort you?
It's quite far away.
I'll find my way.
If you'll excuse me.
Magnificent, isn't she?
Are those real
var'Hama candles?
Yes, Worf,
I traveled to Kronos.
I captured three targs
in the Hamar mountains,
made the ritual
sacrifice at dawn,
came back
to the station,
asked Quark to boil their
shoulders into tallow.
Then, I spent two days
molding them into candles
with my own hands.
I was just asking.
You were
criticizing again.
Relax. She's not
going to reject
a prospective daughter
because the
var'Hama candles
in her welcoming
display were replicated.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Tug son bosh mok
A'Beh, Sirella koH.
E'Gagh vet moh.
What is he doing here?
I meant no disrespect.
Then leave.
Your worthiness to join
our House will now be judged
according to the traditions
of my family.
I am prepared, my lady.
I doubt that.
A Klingon woman would find it
difficult to gain my favor.
For...an alien,
it will most likely
be impossible.
I like a challenge.
I will not have my authority
challenged by you.
That's not what I meant.
If you cannot say
what you mean,
say nothing at all.
The evaluation
will begin tomorrow morning.
Have the traditional meal
prepared before I arrive.
And in the future,
if you cannot trouble yourself
to make real var'Hama candles,
try not to use
such obvious fakes.
You never told me
that your wife
was opposed to this marriage.
Sirella is a woman
of strong convictions.
She believes
that by bringing aliens
into our families,
we risk losing our identity
as Klingons.
That is a prejudiced,
xenophobic view.
We are Klingons, Worf.
We don't embrace
other cultures.
We conquer them.
If someone wishes to join us,
they must honor our traditions
and prove themselves worthy
of wearing the crest
of a Great House.
Jadzia is worthy.
Of course she is.
She's an honorable woman
and a formidable warrior.
You should say that to Sirella.
That's not such a good idea.
I don't want her to think
that I'm interfering
in her domain.
Perhaps I should
speak with her.
Coming from me, it would
not seem like a challenge
to her authority.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
Why?
Well, um...
the truth is...
she doesn't like you
that much either.
Me.
Don't let that
bother you.
I had every right
to bring you into the family
and she's accepted the fact
that there's nothing
she can do about it.
How comforting.
( chuckles )
( laughing )
And they say that
you have no sense of humor.
( laughing )
Phew. I could do
without the heat.
I can't, uh, say much
for the decor either.
Well, it can't be
all fun and games.
I'm sure there has to be
some sort of ritual
we have to go through
before the party begins.
There is going to be
a party, isn't there?
You're asking me?
I can barely say
my name in Klingon.
MARTOK:
Prepare yourselves,
my friends
for a journey
you won't soon forget.
These...
are Ma'Stakas.
What, uh, what do
we do with them?
At the conclusion
of the wedding ceremony
you will use them
to attack Worf and Dax.
Obviously.
Don't you know anything?
The tradition dates back
to the wedding
of Kahless and Lukara
who were nearly killed
by Molor's troops
moments after they were
married.
Until the ceremony,
you should keep these with you
at all times.
SISKO:
I trust
this combat is non-lethal.
It is a symbolic
attack only.
Oh.
That food is not
to be eaten.
Then what is it for?
It is there to tempt us
to break our fast.
Fast?
There are six trials
we must face
on the path to Kal'Hyah.
This is the first--
deprivation.
We now begin a fast
that will continue
until the day of the wedding.
Well, th-that's
four days away.
MARTOK:
It is a short time,
I know, but we must
make the best of it.
What are
the other five trials?
Blood, pain, sacrifice,
anguish...
and death.
Sounds like marriage,
all right.
How would you know?
It is time to begin.
QUARK:
Need more flowers
on the banister.
MALE:
We're ready
with the banner, boss.
( whistles )
Raise it.
You're up early.
I thought writers
slept late.
Not always.
I sold my first
book today.
Really? How much
did you get for it?
It's just a
figure of speech.
The Federation
News Service
is going to publish
a book of my stories
about life on the station
under Dominion rule.
And they're not
paying you?
No.
Well, then you have
my sympathies
and the first round
of drinks is on the house.
Really?
No. It's a figure
of speech.
Look, I want to tell
my dad about the book.
Is he still in
the holosuite?
Oh, yeah.
They're still up there.
What are they doing?
It's a Klingon
bachelor party.
You're a writer.
Use your imagination.
BASHIR:
Alexander.
Grandma?
Guess again.
We're still on the...?
The road to Kal'Hyah,
day 500.
Maybe we should
turn down the heat
you know, for
Alexander's sake.
Oh, no, it's okay.
I, uh...
I just need some water.
Now, you don't want
to push yourself too hard.
You know, turning down the heat
might be a good idea.
The whole point
is to push yourself
to the limits
of your endurance.
( panting )
I will.
I want to travel
the entire path to Kal'Hyah.
Stoke the fire again!
As you wish.
Of course, we cannot expect
you non-Klingons to...
have the same stamina
as we do.
If you wish to quit,
no one will think
any less of you.
Who said anything
about quitting?
Not me.
I like the heat.
That's the spirit.
♪ Kaaa vek ko lee ko ♪
♪ eh to che maH lo ♪
♪ TaH oo-wah kaH esh to
pah deH ah reee! ♪
♪ YaH Bosh-ah! ♪
♪ YaH Bosh tomaH! ♪
Al'qoch
mensaH
t'lang
cho.
Again.
I've done it
three times already.
You continue
to rush through
the ceremony,
your body
position is poor,
and the placement
of the braziers
on their pedestals
is sloppy.
Do you know how heavy
those things are?
A Klingon woman
would not complain.
You wouldn't make
a Klingon woman
do it three times in a row.
I wouldn't have to.
She'd have done it correctly
the first time.
End this now, Jadzia.
Go back to your own people.
They will tolerate
your weaknesses
and your failings
in a way that
a Klingon family
never will.
In our House, you would
always be an alien--
an outsider.
At best, you'd be
an object of pity
but you'd never
be accepted
never an equal
because you can never
truly be one of us.
Ko'ma tlang'goS ak-bay
Hava'dak croosh tovaH
Ko'ma Kahless
Ko'ma Kahless.
But the Second Dynasty ended
when General K'Trelan
assassinated Emperor Reclaw.
For the next ten years,
the Empire was ruled
by a Council elected
by the people.
Modern-day
Klingon historians
refer to this
as "The Dark Time."
But it's interesting to note
that this first and only
experiment
in Klingon democracy
actually produced
several reforms...
You are straying from the saga.
Am I?
Your task is to recite
the complete chronicle
of the women in my family.
I just thought I'd give you
a broader historical
perspective
along the way.
I am familiar
with Klingon history.
Now, return to the story
of my 23rd maternal grandmother
Shenara,
daughter of Emperor Reclaw
in the Second Dynasty.
Well, that's where we run
into a little bit of a problem.
You see, I did some research
and when Emperor Reclaw
was killed,
all of the members
of the Imperial Family
were put to death,
including Shenara.
When the Third Dynasty
was founded ten years later,
a new group of Klingons
were given the titles
and the names of the original
Imperial Family...
to create the illusion
of an unbroken line.
So, the woman
that you think of
as your 23rd
maternal grandmother...
isn't related to you at all.
Your real ancestor's name
was Karana,
a concubine living outside
the Imperial Stables.
My grandmother's name
was Shenara.
That may be
what's been passed down
from generation to generation,
but it has no basis in fact.
But who cares about facts?
The chronicle says
that you have
Imperial blood in your veins,
and that's exactly what
we'll keep telling everyone.
Continue with the saga.
My pleasure.
Hey, Major.
Is it true Dax is having
a party tomorrow night?
Ah, news travels fast.
Well, is it by
invitation or...?
I'm sure you're welcome.
And you can tell Nog
the same goes for him, too.
Great.
Oh, I understand
congratulations are in order
to our newest
published author.
Thank you.
What was all that about?
Nothing.
There they go.
KIRA:
They look so serious.
It's all an act.
They don't want
the rest of us to know
what kind of debauchery
they're up to.
Like what?
It's a Klingon
bachelor party.
Use your imagination.
WORF:
Now begins
the Trial of Blood.
MARTOK:
Let rivers flow from our veins.
Who will be first?
I did not expect it
to be you, Doctor.
Neither did I.
Do not worry.
The pain will last
for only a moment.
Ta-hoo!
( loud, rapid drumming )
Isn't that grand?
Yeah! Whoo!
( applause and cheering )
All right!
He's unbelievable.
He's something.
Lieutenant Manuele Atoa
from the Starship
Sutherland.
I've never seen
anything like that.
Neither have I.
Let's get something to eat.
A woman of many talents.
It's a shame
she's about to waste them all
on that walking frown
she calls a fiancé.
She's too good for him.
I've said that
from the beginning.
Are you jealous?
There's no profit
in jealousy.
That's not a denial.
It's not to be
quoted either.
Oh, don't worry.
So when did
you first realize
you had these
feelings for Dax?
Quark, wait.
Miles?
Yeah?
It's working.
I've had a vision...
about the future.
I can see it so clearly.
What is it?
I'm going to kill Worf.
That's what I'm going to do.
I can see it clearly now.
I'm going to kill him.
Kill Worf.
( coughs )
( loud drumming and
conversations continue )
I've been getting complaints
about the noise.
Someone even
mentioned a fight?
Oh, there was a scuffle
between Morn
and one of the Bolians
but they
worked it out.
How long will this...
party continue?
This party will continue
until further notice
on the personal
authority
of this station's
First Officer
who just happens
to be me.
Mm-hmm.
You're in a good mood.
Well, it's
a good party.
Well...
Odo...
I think we have
a lot to talk about.
I agree.
So let's talk.
Now?
Don't you think we've
put it off long enough?
Enjoy yourselves.
Let's, um...
find someplace
a little quieter.
( yells )
Thanks for the show.
Thanks for getting me
the day off.
Captain Shelby
owed me a favor.
Actually,
owed me several.
In fact, how would
you like to have
another two days off?
Two?
What do I have to do?
Not much.
Just give me something
fun to look at
for the rest
of the evening.
Anything else?
I'll let you know.
SIRELLA:
You!
Leave her
or I'll cut your head off
and hang it from my belt.
I'll take care of this.
( drumming and conversations
stop )
You weren't invited.
It is time
for the Bre'Nan ritual.
I'm busy.
Busy acting
like a Risian slut.
I'm only going to ask
you to leave once.
You will come
with me now and perform
the Bre'Nan ritual
to my satisfaction
or I will cancel your wedding.
Toruk-DOH!
NOG:
Ladies, please.
SIRELLA:
Mok'Ta vor
kash a'VEH!
Why is everyone
standing around?
The party's
just getting started.
Play something!
( drumming resumes )
Double raktajino, extra sweet.
( groans )
What time is it?
1030 hours.
Come on.
Wrong door.
Excuse me, sir.
Jadzia
we need to...
You're mad.
I am concerned.
Yeah, well, I'm hung over.
Can we talk later?
We have a very
serious problem.
Sirella has canceled
the wedding.
She doesn't waste
any time, does she?
She said
you attacked her.
She pulled a knife.
You are forbidden to join
the House of Martok.
So I won't be invited
to the family picnics.
I'll live.
I cannot believe
how you're taking
this so lightly.
Do you hear that?
What?
( muffled voices )
It sounds like voices.
Hi.
ODO:
Is the party over?
You could say that.
It's 10:30.
In the morning?
I'm on duty.
So am I.
It was a great party.
Thanks.
We must deal
with the situation now.
Stop yelling.
My head hurts.
You must go to Sirella
and beg her forgiveness.
I don't beg.
You are allowing
your pride to blind you.
Look who's talking.
You want me to go crawling
to some old hag
just so you can have your
traditional Klingon wedding.
This is about more
than just tradition.
You and I have embarked
on a spiritual journey,
one that will
bind us together
through this life
and into the next.
You cannot turn back now.
Maybe you're on
a spiritual journey, Worf,
but I just want
to get married.
So why don't you go back
to sweating and bleeding
with your friends
in the holosuite,
and when you're done,
meet me in
Benjamin's office
and he'll perform
the ceremony.
If that is your attitude...
perhaps Sirella
was right about you.
There should be no wedding.
That's fine with me.
( door opens, closes )
( whistling )
What's going on?
Haven't you heard?
The wedding's off.
Off? Why?
She says it's because
he's a pig-headed, stubborn man
who puts tradition
before everything else.
He says it's because
she's a frivolous
emotional woman
who refuses to take him
or his culture seriously.
You can see
the problem.
They're both right.
Exactly.
Well... there's only
one thing for it.
Dinner.
I'll get the menu.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Worf...
you've made a grave error.
Perhaps.
Do you still love her?
Of course.
However, in this
case, that...
may not be enough.
Anyone can see that we are
hopelessly mismatched.
She is a Trill;
I am a Klingon.
She has had
five marriages.
This would be my first.
When she is laughing,
I am somber.
When I am happy,
she is crying.
She plays tongo with
the Ferengi bartender.
I can barely stand him.
She mocks everything...
while I take
everything seriously.
She is nothing
like the woman
I thought I would marry.
We are not accorded
the luxury
of choosing the women
we fall in love with.
Do you think Sirella
is anything like the woman
I thought that I'd marry?
She is a prideful,
arrogant, mercurial woman
who shares my bed far too
infrequently for my taste.
And yet...
I love her...
deeply.
Hmm.
We Klingons often tout our...
prowess in battle...
our desire for glory and honor
above all else...
but how hollow is
the sound of victory...
without someone
to share it with?
Honor gives
little comfort
to a man alone
in his home...
and in his heart.
One steak with mushrooms
baked potato, sour cream
and chives.
I should have had that.
One double Altair sandwich,
no mustard...
two bowls of linguini,
Bajoran shrimp
with extra cheese.
One loaf of mapa bread.
Quark, where's
the kava juice?
They're still
squeezing the roots
unless you want replicated.
We'll wait.
SISKO:
What do you think
you're doing?
The wedding's
been called off.
It's back on.
Worf is apologizing
to Jadzia
at this very moment.
Quark, take
it all away.
No food for those
on the path to Kal'Hyah.
No refunds for those
on the path
to Kal'Hyah as well.
Sorry.
Father, what happened?
She refused
to change her mind
and the wedding is still off.
( sighs )
Where is she?
In her quarters.
I'll go talk to her.
Just... keep them away
from the food?
( door chimes )
Come in!
Save your breath.
Worf's gone too far,
and now it's over.
Do you know what
he wanted me to do?
He wanted me to go crawling
on my hands and knees
to Sirella
to beg her forgiveness.
Beg her! Me!
I was once
the Federation Ambassador
to the Klingon Empire.
I negotiated
the Khitomer Accords
before Worf
was even born.
Curzonnegotiated the Accords!
And I've got news for you,
old man.
You're not Curzon anymore.
And what the hell is that
supposed to mean?
It means that you
can't expect Sirella
to treat you like Curzon
just because you carry
his memories.
To her, you're just
a young woman
who decided to marry
into her family.
If it means
you have to bow down
and kiss her boots,
that's exactly what you have
to do, and you knew that.
The moment you decided
to marry Worf,
you knew that sooner or later
you'd have to bow down
and show her the respect
that she's due.
This is Worf's fault--
Worf and his traditional
Klingon wedding.
Well, he may have let
this wedding business
go to his head,
but you are 356 years old.
Compared to you,
Worf is just a kid.
And if you can't abide
by Klingon traditions,
then you never should
have let yourself
fall in love with him
in the first place.
And you are
in love with him.
I wasn't looking
to fall in love.
I was perfectly happy
by myself.
I had friends, a career,
adventure...
Then one day...
this Klingon
with a bad attitude
walked into my life
and the next thing I know,
I'm getting married.
After 356 years
and seven lifetimes...
I still lead with my heart.
You know, that is
what I've always
loved about you.
And I think that's why
Worf loves you, too.
( sighs )
Whatever happened to that
young, callow Ensign
I used to know?
The one who used
to turn to me
for advice all the time?
You know,
the one with hair?
I grew up.
I guess it's time
I grow up, too.
Mmm.
With fire and steel
did the gods forge
the Klingon heart.
So fiercely did it beat,
so loud was the sound,
that the gods cried out,
"On this day
we have brought forth
"the strongest heart
in all the heavens.
"None can stand before it
without trembling
at its strength."
But then the Klingon heart
weakened
its steady rhythm faltered
and the gods said,
"Why have you weakened so?
"We have made you the strongest
in all of creation."
And the heart said...
I am alone.
And the gods knew
that they had erred.
So they went back
to their forge
and brought forth...
another heart.
But the second heart
beat stronger than the first,
and the first was jealous
of its power.
Fortunately...
the second heart
was tempered
by wisdom.
If we join together,
no force can stop us.
And when the two hearts
began to beat together,
they filled the heavens
with a terrible sound.
For the first time,
the gods knew fear.
They tried to flee,
but it was too late.
The Klingon hearts
destroyed the gods
who created them
and turned the heavens
to ashes.
To this very day
no one can oppose the beating
of two Klingon hearts.
Not even me.
Worf, son of Mogh,
does your heart beat
only for this woman?
Yes.
And will you swear
to join with her
and stand with her
against all
who oppose you?
I swear.
Jadzia, daughter of Kela,
does your heart beat
only for this man?
Yes.
And do you swear
to join with him
and stand with him
against all
who would oppose you?
( whispering ):
I swear.
Then let all present
here today know
that this man
and this woman are married.
( applause )
Now?
Not yet.
Patience.
My Lady.
Welcome to the House
of Martok...
my daughter.
Now, Doctor!
( yelling )