What about Captain Boday?
Captain Boday?
You want me to bring
Captain Boday
to your quarters for dinner?
It's just a suggestion.
It's a bad suggestion.
Number one, you used
to go out with Captain Boday;
number two, Worf hates
him; and number three...
and we've discussed this
many times...
Captain Boday has
a transparent skull.
And you don't like
to see a man's brains.
Ops.
What about Dr. Trag'tok?
He's intelligent;
he has a good physique...
and he has
a very opaque cranium.
True,
but his eye bothers me.
Which one?
The middle one.
Oh, really.
You are so obsessed
with appearances.
And sometimes your taste
in men frightens me.
I'll make sure
to tell Worf you said so.
Tell me what?
Don't be so nosy.
Hmm. You could always
invite Odo as a friend.
I'm not ready for that;
Odo's not ready for that.
Let's just forget that
you brought that one up.
Two raktajinos,
extra-strong, and a kava roll.
I'm coming to dinner
alone, got it?
I got it.
Three place settings.
I'll bring the wine.
Captain,
you better get out here.
What is it?
I'm showing a power buildup
in the transporter buffer.
Someone's attempting
to beam into Ops.
From where?
I don't know.
There are no ships
within transporter range.
Are you hurt?
No.
But you'll be
unless you do
exactly what I say.
It can't be.
What do you want?
A fast ship would be nice.
Security...
we have a hostage situation.
Clear a path to Landing Pad A.
Authorization:
Sisko-seven-one-green.
Seven-one-green acknowledged,
Captain.
Your runabout's waiting.
Let's go.
If you hurt her
you will never
leave this station.
I promise you that.
Follow me, and she dies...
Hold it!
Ah-ah.
Not the turbolift.
Someone might cut the power,
and we'd be trapped inside.
Then we walk.
Your, uh, uniform...
I've never seen one like it.
You're not with the Alliance,
are you?
There is no Alliance here.
Then I have crossed
into the alternate universe.
Tell you one thing.
The food's better.
So, I take it you're running
from the Alliance.
Now you know
the story of my life.
So, once you get your ship,
what then?
Believe me, wherever I end up
is going to be a lot better
than where I've been.
I can believe that.
I've spent some time
in your universe.
I'll bet you were
glad to leave it.
Now which way?
That way.
How many levels before
we reach the landing pad?
Fifty-seven.
Oh...
Here we are.
Landing Pad A.
Open it.
I've got a better idea.
Why don't you hand
over that disruptor?
Oh, you've been
so cooperative up to now.
I'd hate to have to kill you.
You're not going to kill me.
Oh, you sure of that?
You're not going
to kill anyone...
not with that disruptor.
Power cell's cracked.
How long have you known?
Since we left Ops.
Then... why
did you come with me?
I needed the exercise.
And I have to get away.
You all right, Major?
I'm fine.
The resemblance to Vedek Bareil
is remarkable.
Well, this is the cleanest
interrogation chamber
I've ever been in.
And believe me,
I've been in quite a few.
I'm glad you're comfortable.
Now, do you mind telling me
where you got ahold of this?
A Terran rebel gave it to me.
Hmm. A multidimensional
transporter device... nice gift.
We were very close.
So when do I get to meet myself?
Meaning what?
Well, this is
the alternate universe, correct?
Everything's the same
but different
which means there's
another Bareil Antos here.
There was.
Was?
He's dead.
You knew him, didn't you?
Then that's why you
seemed to recognize me.
What was he like?
Does that really matter?
He was someone you cared about.
Oh...
Major...
I know I have no right
to ask you this
but you could do me a big favor.
Destroy that device.
Why?
Because then
they can't send me back.
I'm sorry.
I can't do that.
Please, Major.
You've been there.
You know what it's like.
Put me in prison,
in a labor camp,
whatever you want.
Just let me stay.
Now, let me
get this straight, Major.
You're refusing
to press charges.
That's right.
I don't think Bareil
ever intended to hurt me.
Well, I suppose we should
just send him back
where he came from.
No. He doesn't want
to go back to that universe
and I don't blame him.
I know what you're
going through, Major.
When I met the other
Jennifer Sisko
it was very confusing,
to say the least.
I knew she wasn't my wife
but sometimes she would smile
at me a certain way...
and then the light
would hit her eyes...
and it was my Jennifer...
at least that's what
I wanted to believe.
Captain
I know this man
is not Vedek Bareil.
He doesn't talk like him;
he doesn't act like him.
He's a totally different person.
But you still feel
this connection with him
that you can't explain,
don't you?
It's not a problem.
Good.
Just make sure
it doesn't become one.
Major.
I just wanted to say thank you
for putting in
a good word for me.
What are you going to do now?
I'm not sure.
I've been reading up
on your world, and...
it's very different
from the Bajor I know.
Is that where you intend to go?
Well, I'm thinking...
about it.
Did you see that?
People keep staring at me.
It's because the man
that you look like
was loved and respected
by a lot of people.
He was a vedek.
A vedek.
A religious leader.
Imagine me a religious leader.
I'm glad you find it funny.
I'm going to be late
for services.
Wait. I didn't
mean to offend you.
It's just the kind
of life I've led
hasn't been very... spiritual.
In fact, I don't think I've
ever been inside a temple.
Well, now's your chance.
You're welcome to join me.
In there?
I don't think so.
Besides, if I go in there
people are going
to start believing
I really am Vedek Bareil.
That's something
I'd like to avoid.
I can understand that.
What are you doing here?
I figured I could use
a little spiritual guidance.
That's not funny.
It wasn't meant to be.
I plan on making a new
life for myself here.
I'm going to need all
the help I can get.
Tolata impara no takash.
With humility and gratitude,
we accept this gift.
Veshanoo yavar ha iktasho.
What's in the box?
The Orb of Prophecy and Change.
Orb?
A gift from the Prophets.
It can foresee the future or...
a possible future anyway.
Who are the Prophets?
Our Gods.
You do have Gods, don't you?
Of course we do.
You don't sound too sure.
That's because
I leave them alone,
they leave me alone.
Shh!
So what'd you think?
I'm not sure.
It... was an interesting
ceremony, but...
But what?
Everybody seemed
to take it so seriously.
What's wrong with that?
I suppose it must be nice
to have that kind of faith.
I've always preferred
to believe in nothing.
That way
I'm never disappointed.
Oh, that doesn't sound
like much of a life.
Maybe not...
but it's all mine.
Anyway, I'm glad I had
this chance to see you again.
It was...
very enlightening.
Thank you, Major.
Bareil.
Do you like Klingon food?
An hour later
the Klingon guard
returns to my cell.
He puts down what's supposed
to be my "last" meal.
I slip his mek'leth
out of its scabbard
hide it in my shirt.
That night, I used the blade
to deactivate the sensor alarm
my earring
to open the cell door.
By the time
they realized I was gone
I was halfway
to the Ventar system.
That's one hell of a story.
And that is all it is...
a story.
Excuse me?
It was well told
but there was no truth
to any of it.
Oh, you're sure of that.
You want us to believe
that you stole a mek'leth
from a Klingon warrior.
Worf, it's not polite to
accuse the guest of lying.
No, it's all right.
Obviously, I was exaggerating.
Would you like to do the honors?
Mmm. Allow me.
I believe...
this is yours?
What do you
think now, Worf?
Obviously,
Bareil is a better thief
than I gave him credit for.
More bloodwine.
Why not?
You are a lucky woman.
Why is that?
You have good friends.
They liked you.
You think so?
Oh. Well, why do you
sound so surprised?
You must have had
friends back home.
I can think of one.
If you'd rather not
talk about it...
There's not much to say.
She died.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
It happened a long time ago.
This is home.
I'm sorry the evening has
to end on such a sad note.
Would you like to come in?
Have a raktajino?
Her name was Lisea.
I first saw her
on the street in Ilvia.
Oh, I couldn't take
my eyes off of her.
She had the most
attractive little...
money sack
hanging from her waist.
Don't tell me you stole it.
She should've known better
than to carry her money
so carelessly in Ilvia.
It's a very dangerous place.
Turns out, she'd just arrived
from one of the mining camps
in the hills of Dahkur Province.
I come from Dahkur Province.
Only here it's all farmland.
When I met her, she was working
in an Ilvian pleasure center.
And you decided to take
her away from all that.
I taught her how to be a thief.
The funny thing is
she was so grateful.
She felt I saved her life.
Maybe you did.
If anyone was saved,
it was me.
We were having dinner
in a bar one night.
A fight broke out.
Drunken Cardassian
pulled out his disruptor
and started firing.
We were together five years.
And in all that time
I never told her
how much she meant to me.
I know what it's
like to lose someone.
When I activated
that transporter device
I had no idea where I'd end up.
I never thought
I'd be sitting here...
with you.
Two days ago...
all I wanted was to be alone.
Major...
Don't you think it's
time you called me Nerys?
What did you say
these were called?
Alvas.
They grow all over Bajor.
Not my Bajor.
I can't believe
you're still hungry.
After a big Klingon meal
I usually don't eat
for two days.
Ever since I got here,
I can't stop eating.
What is it?
Nothing.
This must be
very strange for you.
You and I here together...
me looking like him.
Fortunately, you're
not anything like him.
You mean
he didn't eat in bed?
Antos was very disciplined.
He had a strict routine
he never deviated from.
He only ate two meals a day.
Simple food.
He used to say
"When you overindulge
the body..."
"You starve the soul."
How did you know that?
I did a little research...
enough to know
that when he died
Bajor suffered a great loss.
I would've given...
my life to save his.
But all I could do
was just stand there
and watch his slip away.
Are you tired?
Not anymore.
Want to get an early breakfast?
Sounds good.
My medical requisitions.
Why didn't you
just download them
into the computer?
Oh, um, I don't know.
Thought I might stretch my legs.
See what was happening in Ops.
Kira hasn't shown up yet.
Kira?
You are so transparent.
What are you talking about?
Your guilt is quite clear,
Doctor.
Guilt? About what?
About medical requisitions?
Don't be ridiculous.
Julian, Kira's personal life
is her own.
We're her friends.
We should respect her privacy.
Good morning, Nerys.
How'd it go last night?
You mean dinner?
We had a great time. Why?
Uh, she means after dinner
but you don't have
to answer that
because we don't want
to invade your privacy.
But if you want to tell us
about it, we'll listen.
It went... well.
I told you.
I never doubted it.
Well, I, uh...
think I should be getting
back to the Infirmary.
Unless, um, there are
any more details forthcoming.
Good-bye, Doctor.
Good-bye.
Worf, any news from
General Martok's scout ships?
They report no Dominion activity
along the border.
Let's hope it stays that way.
Are you seeing him tonight?
At the Bajoran shrine.
That doesn't sound
very romantic.
He's going to have
his first Orb experience.
Your idea, I suppose?
No, actually, it was his.
He's curious about
Bajoran spirituality.
It's a new concept for him.
Well, it's not a midnight
swim in the holosuites
but if it makes you happy.
So, where is this vedek?
He'll be here.
Now stop pacing.
This is an Orb experience,
not an execution.
I just don't want
to disappoint anyone.
That's sweet, but I'm
not going to judge you.
I know that.
I meant the Prophets.
What do I say to them?
You don't have
to say or do anything.
I just...
stare into the Orb.
Actually, it's more like
the Orb stares into you.
Welcome, my child.
Are you ready to proceed?
Yes.
Your pagh is strong.
You are ready to face
the will of the Prophets.
Come.
Thank you. I'm...
not hungry.
Well, that's a change.
When you had
your first Orb experience
did you understand it?
I don't know that anyone
fully understands
an Orb experience...
not at first anyway.
You have to live
with it for a while.
Absorb it.
And then?
And then one day, it...
becomes a part of you
a part of who you are.
I thought I would get
a glimpse of the future.
It was more than that.
It changes you.
There were so many images.
I couldn't keep
track of them all.
He was there.
Vedek Bareil.
We were together, talking,
but...
it was all mixed up.
I-I-I was him.
He was me.
It's all very confusing.
I don't think we should
be talking about this.
If I can't tell you about it
who can I tell?
No one.
An Orb experience
isn't meant to be shared.
I feel as if I could
sleep for days.
Well, that's
a very common reaction.
Why don't you get some rest?
I will.
Nerys...
It's all right.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I was wondering
when you'd get back.
What are you doing here?
I know.
I'm early.
But my curiosity
got the better of me.
Besides, the thought
of you pining away for me
was too much to bear.
Now, tell me...
how's our little plan
progressing?
Couldn't be better.
Right on schedule.
That's just what
I was hoping to hear.
Now...
tell me everything
that's happened
since you got here.
Mmm, later.
I'm too tired.
Right now, all I want
to do is go to bed.
Mmm. Even better.
I said I was tired.
You've never been tired before.
It's been a long day.
I don't think you're pleased
to see me.
Oh, it's her, isn't it?
The Major's gotten to you.
Don't be stupid.
Oh, I'd be disappointed
if you didn't find
the Major intoxicating.
I mean, after all, she is me...
or the next best thing to me.
So...
what did you think of her?
You are crazy.
Oh, we know what I'm like.
What about her?
I am not going to discuss this.
Oh, please.
Please.
I really want to know.
She's wonderful.
Mmm.
Oh, I knew it...
but she's too good for you.
We both are.
I mean, you're nothing
but a petty thief.
I know what I am.
That's it?
That's all you have to say?
I said I was tired.
Oh, Major Kira must...
This has nothing to do
with the Major. I...
I looked...
into the Orb today.
You did?
Oh, how very exciting.
So...
how soon can we
get our hands on it?
The vedeks are holding
a 26-hour vigil in the shrine.
Now, I cannot get near the place
until tomorrow night.
The Orb is
behind a force field keyed
to a decryption matrix.
Oh, which you can bypass.
That's what thieves do.
Oh...
today you're a thief
but tomorrow...
once we bring our prize home...
you'll be
the Bearer of the Orb...
the holy man who unites
the Bajoran people
in a war against the Alliance.
Just call me Vedek Bareil.
Think of it...
the wealth, the power.
You'll be like a god.
You're putting a lot of faith
in that Orb.
So will every other Bajoran.
Oh, we're going to have
such fun.
I can hardly wait.
You do look tired.
You should get some rest.
And tomorrow...
when you see the Major...
give her that...
for me.
Sleep well.
One more.
Coming right up.
What are you two looking at?
Same goes for the rest of you.
I am not Vedek Bareil.
I just want to be left alone.
You heard the man.
Now, leave him be.
Sorry about that.
People can be so rude.
You know, I used to see
the vedek all the time
walking down the Promenade
with Major Kira.
Never came in here, though.
I guess dabo wasn't his game.
It's an amazing resemblance.
Put you in a vedek's robe
and nobody would know
the difference.
Believe me,
there's a difference.
But not to the paying public.
You have a business
proposition for me?
Well, spit it out.
Picture this.
You seated here wearing robes
a long line of Bajorans
waiting patiently
to pay good money
just to meet Vedek Bareil...
maybe touch his hand.
Like I said,
I'm not Vedek Bareil.
A mere technicality.
You're the closest thing
to Vedek Bareil
they're ever going to see
which is why
they're going to love you.
I wouldn't know what to say.
The less the better.
Just nod every once in a while
and smile... benignly.
It's very simple.
Later on, once you get
the hang of it
you might even throw in
a blessing or two.
What do you think?
I've known people like
you my whole life...
nasty, greedy little minds
willing to do whatever it takes
to make money.
I know just how you think.
That's because you
think the same way.
I suppose I am
a lot more like you
than I'll ever be like...
Vedek Bareil.
Perfect.
Then we have a deal?
I'm afraid not.
Why?
Because right now
I don't like either one of us.
It's a shame to see
such a perfect opportunity
go to waste.
Major, any idea where they put
my shipment of Saurian brandy?
Over there.
You heard her.
Your new boyfriend
came into my bar today.
Oh, did he?
He's... a little
different, isn't he?
From what?
From some
of your previous choices.
Don't get me wrong.
I had nothing against
Vedek Bareil or Shakaar
but they were
a little too controlled...
a little too controlling.
They lacked fire, excitement
but this Bareil...
he's different.
He's full of surprises.
Oh, so I take it
that you like him.
Let's just say
I like the idea of you with him.
But let me tell you
something, Major.
You'd better brace yourself.
You're in for a rough ride.
Oh, what are you talking about?
I've been a bartender
for a long time.
I've seen all sorts
of customers...
sad ones, happy ones,
complicated ones.
Uh-huh, and Bareil...
where does he fit in?
He's one of the tormented ones.
Tormented?
No, I don't think so.
Quark, you've had
an Orb experience.
You know what it's like.
Mmm... he had an Orb experience.
Interesting.
Oh, meaning what?
After he left the bar
I saw him hanging around
the Bajoran shrine.
He must have been there
a couple of hours.
Well, he has a lot on his mind.
He probably went there
to think things over.
Either that...
or he was figuring out a way
to rob the place.
What's this?
A union meeting?
Let's get going.
Nice chatting with you, Major.
I hope you two...
are very happy together.
Well, what do you think?
Even I'd have trouble
telling you apart.
Wearing the Major's clothes...
it feels so intimate.
Oh, admit it.
You've never found me
more exciting.
It's like having
the best of both worlds.
Let's try to stay focused,
all right?
We both have jobs to do.
You're right.
We'll celebrate later.
Did you get the com badges?
Ooh, what nimble fingers.
Contact me the minute
you have the Orb.
Right.
You're going to look
so good wearing a crown.
Everything quiet?
Yes, Major.
Good.
I'm sorry.
I need your level-6
authorization code.
Oh, is that really necessary?
It's the new protocol...
the war?
Of course.
Is everything all right?
I must've pulled a muscle
exercising in the holosuites.
It's been bothering me all day.
Would you mind massaging
my shoulders for me?
I could make it an order.
Mmm. A little harder, please.
Ooh, such strong hands.
If only we had
some warm Somata oil.
That would be nice, wouldn't it?
I guess.
You have a lot to learn
about giving a massage.
What's that old saying?
Once a thief?
What are you doing here?
The question is:
Nerys?
How did you know?
I didn't.
You had me completely fooled.
The thief
in search of redemption.
Who could resist that?
Obviously, not me.
Luckily, Quark didn't
fall for your little act.
Now, step away from the altar.
I wish I could, but I can't.
I've come too far.
Then you came a long way
for nothing.
Nerys.
Oh, you look
as beautiful as ever.
You're just full
of surprises, aren't you?
Well, it's only fair.
You had your Bareil;
I have mine.
You were supposed to wait for me
at the transporter pad.
Oh, don't worry.
I have the transporter
keyed to this control.
All I have to do is tap this key
and we're on our way home.
Besides, I couldn't leave
without saying hello to myself.
The transporter sensors
showed that you weren't
alone in the shrine
and I was hoping
it was you, Nerys.
Bareil's smart
but you're smarter.
We really are alike, aren't we?
You can't let her have the Orb.
It's too dangerous.
Will you stop
wasting your breath?
Antos and I are a team.
We're destined to do
great things together.
If we're going, let's go.
You don't have to do this.
Oh, isn't that sweet?
She is still trying
to save your soul.
Of course, you don't have one.
She's right.
I'm not worth saving.
You sound pretty certain
of that.
Look at him.
Really... look at him.
It's important that you see him
for what he truly is.
I do.
So...
you were just using me
to get to the Orb.
Is that what I'm supposed
to believe?
Believe anything you want.
Please, Nerys,
don't embarrass yourself.
You made a mistake.
You let Bareil
make a fool of you.
That's bad enough.
Don't make it worse
by denying what happened.
Just accept it and move on.
Why should I?
It's not true.
You know that as well as I do.
You may have come here
for the Orb
but you found something else.
And people say
that I have a large ego.
Tell her, Antos.
Tell her how you were using her
that everything you
told her was a lie
that every time you touched her
all you could think about
was me.
Oh...
When she wakes up, I'll have
a lot of explaining to do.
And if you don't have the Orb,
she'll kill you.
Maybe.
That'll certainly be
her first reaction
but I've talked my way back
into her good graces before.
I'll be all right.
I guess this is good-bye.
It's for the best.
You know what I saw
when I looked into that Orb?
You and me...
together...
on Bajor.
We had a life...
a family.
What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
Might even work...
for a while.
But eventually,
I'd find some way
to ruin it.
I'm a thief.
I belong with her.
Then you should go.