No, no, it is not there!
Am I the only one here?
Is that it?
Hm-hm-hm? Is that it?
Am I the only one who sees?
Hm, hm, hm, hm?
And what
is that incessant noise?!
Calm down.
Am I talking too fast,
Doctor?
Having trouble keeping up,
hm, hm, hm?
I don't want
to see you get upset, Jack.
Please don't leave
us here, Karen, please!
It's only for a few weeks,
Patrick.
You know why they brought
us here, don't you?
Why they carted us
halfway across the quadrant?
They're going
to experiment on us.
Stop it, Jack.
They want to find out what makes
our genetically engineered
brains tick.
They're going
to cut our heads open
and see what comes out!
He's just trying to scare you.
Don't listen to him.
Now, I told you
why I brought you here,
remember?
Mm-hmm.
To meet that doctor,
Dr. Bashir?
You know.
The handsome one.
He was genetically enhanced
when he was a boy,
just like all of you.
No, no! He's not like us.
I never saw him
at the Institute.
He wasn't locked away, hm-hm,
for being too smart, hm-hm?
He's passed
himself off as normal.
He's Mr. Normal Starfleet man,
mm-hmm.
Mr. Productive Member
of Society.
Well, maybe we can learn
to be just like him.
Wear little uniforms, hm?
Yes, sir!
No, sir!
Thank you, sir!
I don't like it here.
It's going to be all right.
Dr. Bashir is going
to work with you
for a while, that's all.
Just think of it
as a little vacation
from the Institute.
No, no, this is
not happening, no.
It is happening, Jack,
and you're going
to have to try
to make the best of it.
I'm going to make
the best of it.
See the way he's looking at me?
He's in love with me already.
Give me that!
I want to go home.
It's him.
See that?
That's what I'm going to do
to your boyfriend.
Give me the padd.
Sorry.
You're not sorry.
We both know that.
You did it on purpose
because you're upset
but there are better ways
of dealing with being upset.
I'll work on it.
All right, well...
I'll see you all in a few weeks.
Patrick, it's fine.
It's fine.
Go on.
Bye, Sarina.
You all right?
Oh, it's nothing.
Just another run-in with Jack.
Like I said in my report
don't turn your back on him.
Well, we better get you down
to the Infirmary.
I'm fine. You go on in.
They're about as ready
to meet you
as they'll ever be.
I just hope you
have better luck
getting through to them
than I've had.
Hello?
Funny. He doesn't look
like a mutant.
Is that you, Jack?
He knows me.
He knows my name.
I didn't tell him my name.
It's all right.
I just read Dr. Loews' report,
that's all.
I knew that.
Hello, Sarina.
What is he talking to her for?
He read the reports.
She won't answer you.
Didn't you read
the reports? Hm-hm-hm?
Would anyone mind
if I turned on the lights?
if he turns on some lights?
Go ahead, we're not mole people,
you know.
Computer, lights.
Hello.
Lauren.
I know what you're thinking,
Julian
but I'm not that kind of girl.
Bashir, was it? Hm.
Rings a bell, rings a bell.
Bashir, Bashir,
Bashir, Bashir, Bashir...
Ah, got it, got it!
15th-century poet...
Singh el Bashir.
Any relation?
Yes, actually.
His work was totally derivative.
He was a plagiarist.
You knew that.
You had to know that.
Yet you come in here
bragging about it anyway,
hm, hm.
Why? Hm? Hm?
You're the one
who brought it up.
Well, what was I
supposed to do...
just let you get away
with it?! Hm-hm-hm?
That noise!
Tell me, Doctor,
what kind of enhancements
did your parents
have done to you?
Mental abilities, mostly
but they had
my hand/eye coordination
reflexes and vision
improved as well.
Can you do that? Hm-hm-hm?
I doubt it.
Yeah, what happened?
Uh, your parents couldn't afford
the full overhaul, hm-hm?
He turned out all right.
You're not exactly known for
being very discriminating, hm?
I turned you down, didn't I?
And you're still regretting it!
The cube root of 329...
what is it?
6.903.
Very good!
And you didn't even use
your fingers.
He's a mutant,
just like the rest of us.
No, no, no, he is not like us.
He passed as normal.
Is that true?
Did you pass as normal?
My genetic status was
discovered a year ago.
How'd you manage to hide it
for so long?
I did my best
not to exploit my abilities.
Mm-mmm,
so no one would suspect.
Very clever. I'm impressed.
Now, that's not right!
There are reasons why DNA
resequencing is illegal.
There are reasons
why people like us
are barred from serving
in Starfleet.
We have an advantage.
Normal people can't compete.
It's not fair.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I should have
said something sooner.
There are rules...
uh, uh, don't talk
with your mouth full
don't open an airlock
when somebody's inside it
and don't lie
about your genetic status.
No, no, no, you did.
You lied.
You'd lied, and-and then
when you got caught
you cut a deal with Starfleet,
hm, hm, hm, hm?
You-you got yourself
off the hook.
If you'd told the truth
you could have lived with us
at the Institute.
Hm, he's right, you know.
Then they would have
put you away.
They don't put people away
for being genetically
engineered.
No, no, no, no,
they just won't let you
do anything that's worth doing!
No, no, they are afraid
that people like us
are going to take over!
Well, it happened before.
People like us
did try and take over.
Oh, no, no, I knew you
were going to do that.
I knew that you were going
to trot out the Eugenics War.
I'm not trotting out anything.
All I'm saying is
there's a good reason
why we've been barred
from certain professions
but that doesn't
mean we can't be
productive members of society.
Yeah, here it comes...
the "We Can Still Contribute"
speech.
No, no, no, no.
I will not forget
what was done to me.
I will not be
a part of a society
that put me away
for being too smart! No, no!
All right, then.
Seeing as though you have
all the answers already
I'll spare you the speech.
I'm having dinner
with some friends.
What? You think we
don't eat? We eat.
We're going to eat right now.
Hm? Y-Yum-yum.
I'll go set the table.
Don't worry about us.
We'll be fine. Hm.
Thanks for scaring him off.
All I kept thinking was
"There, but for
the grace of God, go I."
How do you mean?
My parents managed
to find a decent doctor
to perform the DNA
resequencing on me.
These four weren't so lucky.
They all suffered
unintended side effects
and by the time
they were five or six
their parents were forced
to come forward
and admit they'd broken the law
so that their children
could get treatment.
Hm. Perhaps they waited
too long.
Yeah. There was nothing
the doctors at the Institute
could do for them.
These cases are so rare.
There's no standard treatment.
I can't imagine
it was a very stimulating
environment for them.
That's what Dr. Loews thought
when she first came
to the Institute.
She got permission to separate
them from the other residents
so that she could work
with them.
Why did she bring them here?
She thought they might respond
to meeting someone
like them who was leading
a normal life.
She was also hoping that one day
they might be able to live
on their own and be productive.
Well, let's hope they
don't become too productive.
Might make the rest of us
look bad.
It is not a laughing matter.
If people like them are
allowed to compete freely
then parents would
feel pressured
to have their children enhanced
so they could keep up.
That's precisely what prompted
the ban on DNA resequencing
in the first place.
Giving them
a chance to contribute
doesn't necessarily
mean sanctioning
what was done to them.
They didn't ask
to have their DNA tampered with.
They were only children.
And why should they be excluded
just because their parents
broke the law?
You're right.
It's not quite fair...
but even so, it seemed like
a good way to discourage
genetic tampering.
Besides, it's not as if
we're trying to exclude them
from anything.
We're just... talking about...
you know, limiting
what they're allowed to do.
Like joining Starfleet.
Exactly.
Are you saying
that I shouldn't be allowed
to wear this uniform?
Well, you are an exception.
Ah, an exception.
I should be used to that.
I've been one all my life...
first, because
of the DNA resequencing
and now, because I've been
allowed to join Starfleet.
Perhaps I should not
have said anything.
No. No, it's all right.
Well,
does anyone care to speculate
about what Gul Damar
is going to say in his speech?
Nothing we're going to like,
I'll bet.
It should be starting
any minute.
If he's going to announce
another new battle offensive
it's going to spoil dessert.
Can you hear me?
H-Hello, calling Dr. Bashir.
Jack...
Hello. Anybody there? Hm-hm?
Did you give them access
to the com system?
Hello? Hello? Dr. Bashir? Hm?
No, they must have
broken in somehow. Oh!
I'd love to stay and chat
about our impending doom, but...
I can't take it!
Would you do something
about that noise!
What noise?
What kind of sick game
are you people playing, hm?!
What are you talking about?
Can't you hear it?!
We complained, and two
very cute engineers came by
and said there
was nothing wrong.
Wait a minute.
Is it a kind
of high-pitched whine?
Yes! Thank God!
See? I told you
we weren't crazy.
Hm-hm-hm?
You are a mutant.
You are.
Now, do something
about that noise
or I will snap her neck.
I called Chief O'Brien.
Now, let her go.
Maybe I'll wait
until he gets here.
If you don't let her go
I'll tell the Chief
the noise went away
by itself.
You think I want
to be doing this?
I'm just making sure
things get done.
Unbelievable.
This is the thanks I get.
Are you all right?
Come in.
Miles...
I wonder if you could find out
what's making that noise.
I know you can't hear it,
but it's there...
probably a sympathetic
vibration
in the power coupling
or something.
What do you know?
You're right.
Well, why don't you fix it,
dear fellow, dear fellow?
Well, why don't you fix it
before I go mad?!
He's married.
Too bad.
Sounds like the plasma
flow's out of sync.
You're right.
Better realign it.
I was just thinking that.
Yeah. Ooh!
It's about to start.
Almost finished.
There.
Finally.
Ah!
Much better.
Thank you, Chief.
Fellow citizens
these are great days
for Cardassia.
Together,
with our Dominion allies
we have given our enemies
cause to fear us once more.
Can't argue with that.
Who's he?
It's Damar, the new head
of the Cardassian government.
"Uneasy lies the head
that wears the crown."
He's sad.
Ashamed is more like it.
Why do you say that?
Shh!
...we are poised to make
another bold step
to ensure our future.
Peace!
Looks like a man
who doesn't sleep.
"Methought I heard a voice cry,
'sleep no more!
'Damar does murder sleep."'
He's killed someone!
Someone close to him.
How could they know that?
...shed their blood
to defend their home.
Their sacrifice must not be
in vain.
The peace we seek
will honor their memory
and preserve the gains
for which they gave their lives.
I challenge the Federation
to answer my call for peace.
I am ready at any time
to meet with its representatives
to discuss how we can put an end
to hostilities.
As your leader...
Pretender! You don't belong
on that throne, and you know it.
...everything in my power
to protect Cardassia.
Someone's making him say
all this. He doesn't want to.
...forward into a new era.
This I vow
with my life's blood...
for my sons...
for all our sons.
Did any of you know who
Damar was before today?
No, no, no,
but it's obvious who he is.
The pretender...
...who-who killed the king
and seized the throne.
Not the king.
He's still alive.
Oh, the queen, maybe...
- Or a princess.
- Mmm.
Yes. Ziyal.
That's Gul Dukat's daughter.
And now, the pretender
finds himself in league
with a-a-a dark knight
that he can't control. Hm, hm?
Weyoun?
It's not a bad story.
Epic, really.
What else can you tell us?
Hm, hm?
It was amazing.
They pieced together
the entire story
of how Damar came to power.
Weyoun is the dark prince
Gul Dukat is the deposed king
Damar is the pretender
to the throne, and Ziyal is
the innocent princess
he murdered.
And now the pretender is wracked
with guilt over what he's done.
And they got all this just
from watching Damar's speech?
Oh, they were fascinated
by the whole thing.
They kept bombarding me
with questions
about Cardassia and the war.
I've never seen them so engaged.
And you want
to keep them engaged.
I'd like to try.
I'm just running
out of material.
What do you mean?
Well, they've already gone
through everything
the computer has
on Cardassia and the Dominion.
Roll out the red carpet.
Visitors?
Starfleet has decided to listen
to what Damar has to say.
He and Weyoun will be arriving
in the morning
and I am the lucky one
who gets the chance
to sit across the table
from them.
That's great!
It's hard to believe
that the Dominion
really wants peace.
I wouldn't be surprised
if they were
just stalling for time
in order to regroup.
Sir, is there any chance
I can get a transcript
of the negotiations?
You can do better than that.
The Dominion has insisted
on recording the proceedings
so that everyone can see
that their desire for peace
is sincere.
Perfect.
You shouldn't have agreed
to that, Benjamin.
Now you have to be
on your best behavior.
Hm.
So, the pretender
and his dark knight
are coming to the station,
hm, hm?
And the story's not over, eh?
Peace talks
could be interesting.
I'd say so
and the best part is
we're going to have
ringside seats.
Mmm-mmm!
Ah, Major!
Welcome to Deep Space 9.
How nice to see you again.
Can I give you a word
of advice, Weyoun?
By all means.
You're welcome
to play your little
"we're all friends here" game
with me
but I wouldn't try it
with Captain Sisko.
He's not in the mood.
We're on a mission
of peace, Major.
Maybe he should get in the mood.
This is the border as it existed
before hostilities broke out.
This is the border
we are now proposing.
This arrangement would award
disputed star systems
to the side that already has
effective control over them.
On the balance, we are
giving up more than you.
Computer, freeze program.
Computer...
Hi. Uh, listen.
Go to native language mode
and replay time code
7-6-1 through, uh, uh...
7-6-9, hm, hm.
Eee-ja maa'na hoo'va-baa'li
jen'ku'rada sen'to.
Got you!
Did you hear that,
hm, hm, hm?
He used the passive
voice transitive, hm, hm.
Since when could you
speak Dominionese?
Hm, since this morning.
That phrasing is only used
to make a request
not a statement.
They are up to something,
hm, hm, hm.
What is it, Patrick?
Did you see something?
You can tell us.
They want the Kabrel system.
How do you know?
They kept avoiding it
with their eyes.
Are you sure?
They kept avoiding it.
Told you they were
up to something, hm, hm?
End program.
All right, they want
the Kabrel system, but why?
I don't know,
but they're willing
to give up a lot to get it.
The mizainite deposits
on Holna IV alone
are enough to keep their
shipyards running for years.
Yes, yes, yes, that's typical
Dominion strategy.
They offer to give up
something valuable
in order to hide the fact
that they want something
even more valuable
in the long term, hm, hm, hm.
See, that's how they think.
Big picture.
They don't worry about what's
going to happen tomorrow.
No, no, no.
They're thinking long term.
They're thinking what's going
to happen a year from now
a-a-a decade, a century,
hm, hm, hm, hm, yes, yes.
There must be something special
about the Kabrel system.
Nothing on the first planet
but some simple
protozoids
and tri-nucleic fungi.
The second planet
has some cormaline deposits
but they're common enough.
Okay, okay, okay, maybe
there's another reason, hm.
Does it have
any strategic value, hm, hm?
Not that I can see.
They wouldn't want
to build a base there.
Why not, why not?
Hm, hm?
Seems perfectly suitable.
It's not an optimum situation.
It's a binary system.
There's a lot
of ionic interference there.
All right, all right,
forget it.
Does this have anything to do
with what we're talking about,
Sarina?
Can we take it?
...like an ancient technology,
hm, hm, hm?
There's no evidence
of anything like that.
Any idea what this might mean?
Chemistry was never
my strong suit.
What is it?
It shows
how you can break down
tri-nucleic fungus
to make yridium bicantizine
one of the active ingredients
in ketracel-white.
That's why the Dominion wants
the Kabrel system
so that they can manufacture
the drug
right here
in the Alpha Quadrant.
According to our calculations
they'll be able
to manufacture enough
to supply the Jem'Hadar
indefinitely.
I was going to recommend
that the Federation accept
the proposed border.
It could've cost us
the Alpha Quadrant.
Actually, sir,
we should give them Kabrel.
Why is that?
If we don't
the Dominion
will be forced to attack
before their stockpile of white
runs out.
Here are
the casualty projections.
As you can see,
an attack would result
in devastating casualties
for both sides.
Y-You're suggesting we stall?
It will buy us time
to rebuild our defenses
and bring the Romulans
into the alliance.
The Romulans.
According to our analysis...
there it is...
they'll vote to abandon
their nonaggression pact
with the Dominion
at next year's plenary session.
By which time,
internal pressures
between the Cardassians and
the Dominion will have erupted
and after three years
six months and 27 days,
we predict that, uh...
Hang on a minute, Doctor.
How'd you come up with all this?
Two days ago,
you said these people
were impossible to deal with.
Now they're
turning out projections
that it would take
Starfleet Intelligence months
to come up with.
We're mutants.
I know.
We're not exactly qualified
for this kind of work
and it could be said that, uh...
it is beyond the limits
of what people like us
should be allowed to do.
But I think if you allow me
to walk you
through our analyses
you'll be impressed.
All right, Doctor, go ahead.
Thank you, sir.
The way
our statistical analysis works
the further
into the future you go
the more accurate
the projection.
It's based on a kind
of nonlinear dynamics
whereby small fluctuations
tend to factor out over time.
The net result is...
Just a minute, Doctor.
Why don't we go back
to the beginning
and take me through this
step-by-step...
nice and easy.
Gladly, sir.
Captain Sisko said he
would take our analyses
to Starfleet Command right away.
Imagine that...
Starfleet Command. Hm.
All those admirals.
It's a party!
It is now.
We need music.
Computer, music.
Make it grand.
A waltz.
Ah!
Care to dance?
Coward.
He tried.
I meant her.
Come in.
Chief.
What a pleasant surprise.
I, uh...
I need to replace
that power coupling.
Don't mind us.
Hi.
No, thanks.
It's a party.
No, I need to get to work.
I didn't mean to...
It's just that I-I need to get
this coupling replaced.
What did you do, Chief?
Nothing!
What's the matter, Patrick?
He doesn't like me.
Well, sure, I do.
See?
The Chief doesn't like
any of us.
- Do you, Chief?
- Julian...
He's just jealous
you're spending
so much time with us.
His wife's away.
He misses his friend.
I do not.
It's all right, Julian.
Go play with your friend.
We'll be fine.
You want me to play with you,
do you, Chief?
No!
Yes, you do.
Come on, let's go to Quark's.
I-I'm going to need those.
No, you don't.
There's nothing wrong
with that power coupling.
Well...
it's... going to have
to be replaced sometime.
Ready?
Ready. Yeah.
I'm sorry.
The last thing in the world
I wanted to do was upset them.
Oh, it's all right.
The only reason
Patrick gets so emotional...
is because he likes you.
He does?
Oh, yeah, they all do.
What? Because I got rid
of that noise?
Oh, no, it's not just that.
They feel comfortable
being around you.
What was the word Jack used?
"Uncomplicated."
Uncomplicated.
Oh, yes, they're
amazingly insightful.
They have ways of seeing things
other people don't.
And saying things
Yeah. They are pretty candid,
aren't they?
They sure are.
Funny thing is
I'm actually beginning
to enjoy their company.
Hey! What are you doing?
Get back!
You know, I was thinking.
Starfleet Command
might do all right
to take them on
as a team of advisers.
Oh, I don't know.
Oh, I can't imagine them
in a room
with a bunch of admirals
unless they're going
to teach them how to dance.
We were celebrating.
Yeah, whatever.
Ah, they really
are quite brilliant, though.
I mean, once we actually started
working, it was incredible.
We were all
on the same wavelength...
talking in shorthand, finishing
each other's sentences.
I've never had that
with anyone else.
Well, after being with them,
I can understand
how the rest of us must seem
a little uncomplicated.
Well, I wouldn't say
that exactly.
More like... slow.
Ha-ha. Must be very
frustrating for you.
I don't mind.
Makes me feel superior.
Oh, glad to be of service.
Ah, I appreciate it.
It's not always easy walking
amongst the common people.
Ah, it's probably best
to keep your expectations low,
huh?
Ha! That way
we can surprise you
every now and then.
Another game?
Sure. But do I have
to stand so far back?
Oh, I-I-I make one lucky shot
and you're ready
to come down to my level.
I like to win, just
like the next man.
Get back there.
Come on.
I've got good news.
Starfleet Command was so
impressed with our analysis
they've agreed
to let us have access
to classified information
regarding Starfleet's
battle readiness.
Is something wrong?
We have new
long-term projections.
You-you better take a look.
You're not going to like it.
Well? Hm, hm?
Everything checks out.
I was hoping
you were going to find a flaw.
Nope.
So then you agree
with our conclusion, hm, hm?
It's inescapable.
There's no way the Federation
is going to be able
to beat the Dominion.
We have no choice.
We're going to have
to surrender.
Surrender to the Dominion...
not on my watch.
Sir, I understand how you feel.
I don't like it
any more than you do
but it's the best option.
We've run dozens
of different scenarios.
Even if something
unlikely were to happen
tilting the scales
in our favor...
such as an anti-Dominion
coup on Cardassia...
we'll still lose this war.
But that doesn't mean
we just give up and roll over.
But if we fight
there will be over
900 billion casualties.
If we surrender, no one dies.
Either way,
we're in for five generations
of Dominion rule.
Eventually a rebellion will
form, centering on Earth.
It'll spread...
and within another generation
they'll succeed
in conquering the Dominion.
The Alpha Quadrant will unite
and a new, stronger Federation
will rule
for thousands of years.
But since we can't win this war
why don't we save
as many lives as we can?
I know it's difficult to accept.
I don't accept it.
Your entire argument
is based on a series
of statistical probabilities
and assumptions.
They're not just assumptions.
If you want me to take you
through the equations
I will.
Even if I knew
with a hundred percent certainty
what was going to happen
I wouldn't ask an entire
generation of people
to voluntarily give up
their freedom.
Not even to save
over 900 billion lives?
Surrender is not an option!
Now I'm happy to hear
your group's advice
on how to win this war
but I don't need your advice
on how to lose it.
We can't win this war.
I don't care if the odds
are against us.
If we're going to lose
then we're going
to go down fighting
so that when our descendants
someday rise up
against the Dominion
they'll know
what they're made of.
With all due respect, sir
aren't you letting your pride
get in your way?
All right, Doctor...
you've made your recommendation.
I'll pass it on
to Starfleet Command.
Without adding your voice to it,
they'll dismiss it out of hand.
I'm counting on it.
So we go down fighting.
How terribly courageous of us.
What do you think?
It's pretty grim.
It's not just grim...
it's hopeless.
We can't beat them, Miles.
Well, it doesn't look
like it, does it?
We have to avoid
a long, drawn-out war.
You mean surrender?
I know...
it's an ugly word
but the facts are facts.
I don't know, Julian.
Don't tell me you agree
with the Captain.
I suppose I do.
Well... is there some
part of the analysis
y-you didn't understand?
Because if there is,
I-I-I'd be happy to explain.
I understood it perfectly.
Believe it or not.
That's not what I meant.
All I'm saying is
that you have to look
at the bigger picture.
Well, I'm trying, but
maybe I'm too uncomplicated
to see it properly.
I didn't say that.
You don't have to.
The way you're acting...
you think nobody
with half a brain
could possibly
disagree with you.
Frankly, I don't
see how they can.
Well, I can see two possible
explanations for it.
Either I'm even more
feebleminded
than you ever realized
or you're not as smart
as you think you are.
Good, good, stop.
One more!
Dabo!
Looks like your lucky day.
Please.
You and I both know
these games of chance
are no such thing...
the odds are
in the house's favor.
Shh. Don't say that.
People are trying to have fun.
Sooner or later, no matter
how perfectly I play
no matter how well
I hedge my bets
I'm going to lose.
Why are you trying to spoil
everyone's good time?
Look around.
These people are
enjoying themselves.
Half of them know the
odds are against them
but they don't care.
They're here because they want
to believe they can win.
Is that so bad?
They're fools.
Why don't you just
take your winnings
and call it a day?
Because I'm trying
to prove a point.
There is no way to win.
Stop saying that.
There! You see?
We're all as good as dead.
Doctor... take it easy.
It's just a game.
You're right.
It's not as if 900 billion lives
were at stake.
I just got word.
Starfleet rejected
our recommendations.
I knew it!
It's kind of a relief
in a way.
I mean, who wants
to wave a white flag?
They're the cowards.
They don't have the courage
to see the truth.
You may be right
but there's nothing we can do.
No, no, no, we can't
just take this lying down.
The stakes are too high.
We've got to take matters
into our own hands.
How, Jack?
What can we do?
We can't force
Starfleet to surrender.
If we can't head off the war
then there might be a way
to make it a lot less bloody.
How?
Look at this...
Starfleet battle plans,
uh, fleet deployments.
Do you know what the Dominion
could do with this information?
They could take the Alpha
Quadrant in a matter of weeks.
With a lot fewer
Federation casualties
than in a drawn-out war.
There wouldn't be more than
two billion casualties.
That's a lot better
than 900 billion.
Wait a minute!
It's one thing for us
to try and avert a war
but it's quite another
for us to take it on ourselves
to trigger an invasion
that's going to get
a lot of people killed.
It's not our place to decide
who lives and who dies.
We're not gods.
Maybe not, but we're
the next best thing.
Can you hear yourself?
That's precisely
the kind of thinking
that makes people afraid of us.
I don't care.
I'm willing to make
this decision.
It's not our decision
to make.
We presented our case
to Starfleet.
They rejected it.
Case closed.
Not closed!
We're going through with this.
Well, I'm not going to be
a party to treason.
Call it what you want,
but I am willing to do it
if it means saving
billions of lives, hm, hm.
So are you with us? Hm, hm?
No! Haven't you been listening?
Fine!
Mmm...
So how do we contact
the Dominion?
Still at it, I see.
I've been looking over
Sisko's latest counterproposal.
We don't seem to be
getting anywhere with him.
Not very encouraging,
is it?
I don't know why you had me
call for peace talks
in the first place.
My, my. How quickly
you've taken to your new role.
And to think,
only a short time ago
you were nothing more
than Gul Dukat's Adjutant.
I appreciate the faith
you've shown in me.
Then show some faith in me.
Don't be like your predecessor,
second-guessing my every move.
It should be clear to you by now
that no one is irreplaceable.
Now...
I just received
a very interesting message
from an unidentified party
claiming to have
some information
that could be
very beneficial to us.
What sort of information?
I don't know
but we're going to find out.
Computer...
Computer, respond.
Sarina, where is everyone?
Did they arrange a meeting
with the Dominion?
Listen, we have to stop them
before it's too late.
Untie me.
Please, Sarina.
You don't want the deaths
of so many people on your hands.
It's Jack, isn't it?
Are you worried
what he'll think?
I've seen the way
you look at him
when you think
no one's watching.
I know how much you care
but if you don't help me
stop them
you know what's going to happen?
They're going to be arrested
and charged with treason
and you're never going to see
any of them again.
You're never going to see
Jack again.
I'm Patrick.
Patrick!
Come on.
Hello, everyone.
He's not supposed to be here.
No, no, no, he's not.
I-I don't understand.
Well, why don't we all go back
to your quarters
and I will explain it to you.
No. We've got to do this.
Lives are at stake.
Don't interfere, Julian.
You have no right.
You're in enough trouble
already, Jack.
Don't make it any worse.
Now, we can do this
the easy way...
or the hard way.
It's up to you.
Where are they?
They'll be here.
This is ridiculous.
Sneaking into a storage bay
for a secret meeting.
I'm not some agent
of the Obsidian Order.
I'm the leader
of the Cardassian Empire.
Don't let it go to your head.
You serve only at the
Dominion's pleasure.
Besides, I think it's exciting.
They're here.
Odo?
Yes, I know.
I honor you with my presence.
We... seem to have
gotten ourselves lost.
Mm-hmm.
They're not coming.
Who's not coming?
I had a feeling
you were going to say that.
Shall I escort you
to your quarters?
Captain Sisko has decided
not to press charges.
You won't be going to prison.
What are they going to do
to us?
Nothing bad.
You'll be going back
to the Institute together.
It doesn't matter
what happens to us.
Don't you realize
what you've done, hm?
I've kept you
from committing treason.
Are we supposed to thank you?
900 billion people
are going to die.
You don't know that.
Didn't you sit here
and go through the
projections with us?
Hm, hm, hm? Didn't you?
He was here, Jack.
I remember.
Maybe our projections
were wrong.
How can you say that?
We factored in
every contingency, hm.
Every variable.
The equations don't lie.
You! You.
You ruined everything.
What do you make of that, Jack?
Why didn't you anticipate that?
Why didn't you factor
her into your equation?
Because you thought
you knew everything
but you didn't even know
what was going to happen
in this room.
One person derailed your plans.
One person changed
the course of history.
Now, I don't know about you
but that makes me think
that maybe, just maybe
things may not turn out
the way we thought.
I heard what happened.
It was a pretty close call.
Yeah. Luckily, I managed
to intercept them in time.
No, that's not what I meant.
I was talking about
when you had to decide
whether or not
to meet with the Dominion.
It can't have been
easy for you.
I know how you wanted to try to
save as many lives as possible.
That's probably what makes you
such a good doctor.
Fortunately, this doctor
is also a Starfleet Officer.
We thought we were so smart.
We thought we could predict
the future.
It was my fault
not theirs.
I should never have let things
go so far.
If I hadn't been so bent on
trying to prove to the world
that they had something
to contribute...
They did contribute.
It seems to me we've become
far too complacent
about the Dominion.
We may have driven them back
into Cardassian space
but we haven't beaten them yet.
I can only hope.
Well, the odds
are stacked against us.
All we can do
is give it our best shot.
You're not going to cause
any more trouble, are you?
Not this time.
I'll double-down.
Risky.
Maybe there's a better bet
but sometimes when the odds
are so stacked against you
you've just got
to take a chance.
I admire your courage.
Dabo!
Well, what do you know?
We have a winner.
O'Brien to Bashir.
Go ahead.
You wanted to know when
a certain transport was leaving.
Oh, thanks.
There is one problem, though.
We've got some passengers
that are refusing to board
unless you come see them.
I didn't think
you'd want to see me again.
Believe me
I wouldn't mind
if our predictions
turned out to be wrong.
Jack's still furious, but...
I didn't want to leave
without saying good-bye.
Will you come visit us?
What?
Oh, uh, yeah, I'd like that.
You did the right thing,
you know.
One of these days,
he'll understand that.
So... you ready to go?
Not so fast.
There's one thing
I need to know, Doctor.
If-if we can come up with a way
to beat the Dominion
will you listen?
I can't think of anything
I'd like better.
Good.
Good, good, all right,
let's go then.
Let's go.
Bashir to O'Brien.
Four to beam out.