Just set them on the bar.
Morn, no touching.
You know what this is?
Three cases of syrup of squill.
I love syrup of squill
on my groatcakes
but I haven't seen a jar
in over a year.
No one has.
Does that mean
the drought on Balancar is over?
There never was a drought
on Balancar.
It was all a ploy
by their agricultural
consortium.
They've been stockpiling squill
in order to drive the price up.
That's dishonest.
I couldn't agree more.
You see, I once did business
with the nephew of the cousin
of the stepsister of a friend
of the secretary to the
consortium's chief accountant.
Nephew... cousin...
stepsister...
friend...
Yeah, that's right.
And he told me in passing
that the accountant
had bought himself
a very nice pair
of Ferengi rain slippers.
And if there was a drought,
he wouldn't need rain slippers.
My thoughts exactly.
So, I set up a meeting
with this accountant
and I told him
that he either provide me
with a shipment of syrup
or I would expose
their deception
to the entire Quadrant.
Tomorrow morning, we are having
a special on groatcakes
topped with syrup of squill.
That is, for everyone
who can afford it.
What are you standing
around for?
Get these crates
into the storeroom.
This stuff is worth
its weight in latinum.
Which reminds me of another
little economic episode of mine.
It happened say, oh,
11 or 12 years ago
shortly before I
came on the station.
Dax! Julian!
You're back.
I was so worried.
I told you we'd be okay.
Then why all the secrecy
about your mission?
We weren't supposed
to talk about it.
Ah, but it's okay now.
The mission's over.
We've been debriefed.
We took the Defiant
behind enemy lines.
We're the first
reconnaissance mission
into Cardassian space
since the Dominion's retreat.
Well, the first one
to make it back, anyway.
And if that isn't reason
to celebrate
I don't know what is.
Three synthales.
Coming right up.
Something wrong, Quark?
Yes, something's wrong.
A bunch of self-satisfied
Starfleet officers...
just stole my audience.
They're not just
Starfleet officers.
They're heroes.
Let's face it, Quark.
There's nothing heroic
about earning profit.
There is on Ferenginar.
We're not on Ferenginar.
The Nagus...
calling me now?
Oh, he must have found out
about the squill.
I have to send him a jar.
No. Better make it a dozen.
He loves squill.
Oh, there you are.
I've been looking all over
the station for you.
Well, you found me.
Now you go hide,
and I'll search for you.
Rom, brace yourself.
I have bad news.
Our mother's been taken prisoner
by the Dominion.
Moogie...
a prisoner?
It gets worse.
The Nagus wants me
to rescue her.
You?
Rescue Moogie?
From the Dominion?
Yep.
Uh-oh.
"Uh-oh" is right.
So, how do you plan
on rescuing Moogie?
You mean, how do we
plan on rescuing Moogie?
I don't recall you saying
the Nagus
wanted me to go along.
Maybe he doesn't, but I do.
Besides, Ishka's your mother,
too.
And I love her,
but I can't go with you.
I'm a married man.
I have responsibilities
and my responsibilities
don't want me to die.
I don't want to die either,
so let's just concentrate
on the reward
the Nagus is offering.
Reward?
50 bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
50 bars?!
Ow.
Which I'm willing
to share with you.
An even split?
Absolutely!
30 bars for me and 20 for you.
That's not even.
It is when you include
my finder's fee.
Right.
There's one thing
I still don't understand.
How did the Dominion
get ahold of Moogie?
They captured the transport ship
she was on.
But she's a female.
They're forbidden to travel
off of Ferenginar.
Moogie's an exception.
The Nagus gave her
special dispensation
to travel to Vulcan
for her operation.
What operation?
She wanted to have
her ears raised.
I had no idea.
That she was so vain?
That the Nagus
could be so generous.
He certainly is.
But why is he being
so good to Moogie?
Brother, there's something
I need to tell you.
You mean, that ten
bars of latinum
is an overly generous
finder's fee?
I already know that.
It's about the Nagus and Moogie.
What about them?
They're lovers.
No...
It's been going on
for over a year.
No!
She's his secret
financial advisor.
She helps him run
the entire Ferengi Alliance.
No!
Would you stop saying that?
May I help you, gentlemen?
I was following you.
We must have taken a wrong turn.
It looks that way.
Much better.
You know, Brother,
I've been thinking.
We can't rescue Moogie from
a Dominion internment center.
Not alone, anyway.
You're right.
We'll need help.
We could put together
a commando team...
gather the toughest
mercenaries we can find...
Nausicaans, Breen, Klingon!
Shh!
We don't need Nausicaans,
Breen or Klingon.
Hu-mans?
We'll just use Ferengi.
Then we'll all die!
No, we won't!
Ferengi can be just
as tough as Klingons.
- They can?
- Of course they can.
They just need the opportunity,
the training
and a couple of bars
of latinum as incentive.
Coming out of my share,
I suppose.
No!
We'll split the reward
with whoever joins us...
all... 20 bars of it.
But the Nagus offered 50.
As far as anyone else is
concerned, he said 20.
20 it is, then.
Now the only question is:
Who's our first recruit?
Not me.
But Nog...
Moogie needs you.
Not to mention your Nagus.
They need you, we need you...
say you'll join us!
Please.
I'm a Starfleet Officer.
I can't go running off with you
on some half-baked
rescue mission.
I have duties to perform.
But you know
how to fire a phaser.
Forget it, Rom.
Don't beg.
Too bad, though.
We were going to make you
Strategic Operations officer.
You mean, like Commander Worf?
Exactly like Commander Worf.
Think of it, Nog.
You'll devise the tactics
come up with a plan of action.
You could be the team's
drill instructor.
Put us through our paces,
prepare us for combat.
Turn us into soldiers.
That's a big job.
That's why we need you.
How big is the team?
Right now?
Now, remember, Leck is
not your typical Ferengi.
His priorities are
different than ours.
I understand, Brother.
No, you don't, but you will.
I hope this is a secure channel.
I followed your instructions
to the letter.
Mmm, very good.
Who do you want eliminated?
It's not that kind of job.
Then why call an Eliminator?
What's an Eliminator?
Shh. I'm putting together
a little rescue mission
and I'd like you
to be part of my team.
I work alone.
You'll be paid in latinum.
I don't care about latinum.
You're right.
His priorities are different.
All right.
Forget the latinum.
I've been told you
like the opportunity
to test your abilities.
I enjoy a challenge.
Then you should know this...
that the person
we're going to rescue
is being held by the Dominion.
The Dominion?
Should be quite a challenge.
Hmm.
How the mighty have fallen.
Cousin Quark.
I heard you were arrested
on Thalos VI for vagrancy.
It's all your fault.
I was a thriving
weapons merchant...
until I went into business
with you.
You ruined me.
If I ever get out of here,
Cousin
I'll make you pay
for what you did to me.
Lower the force field.
Now, what exactly is it
you were going to do to me?
I don't understand.
Quark paid your fine.
You're a free man.
What do I have to do in return?
Earn some latinum.
Tell me more.
On the bar you will find a padd
with the schematic of
a Dominion internment center.
You may now examine
the schematic.
How can we be sure
these schematics are accurate?
Sir.
Oh, no need to stand
on formality here.
Just call me Leck.
No, I meant
you should call me "sir."
Don't be ridiculous.
You mean
"Don't be ridiculous, sir."
Gentlemen, please.
Let's not squabble.
We're a team, Nog.
We're a team, sir.
Stay out of this.
Listen to me, Nog...
That's it. I quit.
You can't quit.
This is not a game.
How are we supposed to get
to this "internment center,"
anyway?
By ship.
Do we have a ship?
We'll get one.
We don't have a ship?
I said, we'll get one!
How?
We'll find one.
Where?
I don't know!
Think of it as a challenge.
Liquidator Brunt!
That's ex-Liquidator Brunt.
Thanks to your brother
I'm no longer with
the Ferengi Commerce Authority.
A child...
a moron...
a failure...
and a psychopath.
Quite a little team
you put together.
What do you want, Brunt?
I'm here to sign up.
I'm going to help you
rescue your mother.
What?
How do you know about Moogie?
I know a lot of things.
Ah... you think if you
help save my mother
the Nagus will give you
your old job back.
When do we leave?
We're not leaving.
Not with you.
That's one thing
we can all agree on.
Nobody likes Liquidators.
Or even ex-Liquidators.
The team has spoken.
Besides, there's a 20-bar
reward to consider.
Better to split it
five ways than six.
Fine.
I'll just get in my ship
and leave.
Did you say ship?
That's right.
Why?
Now we are six.
Don't move!
You're surrounded.
Don't shoot!
I surrender!
No, no, no!
Computer, freeze program.
Reset Jem'Hadar.
I think we're getting better.
No, you're not.
This is the eighth run-through
and you haven't been able
to hit a single Jem'Hadar.
And you shot Moogie!
I saw we weren't
going to rescue her
so I put her out of her misery.
Who invited him along?
Maybe we should start off
with something easier.
Like what?
Like a ambushing
a couple of Bolians.
You couldn't ambush a Bolian
if he was blindfolded
and tied to a tree!
That's enough!
Get out of here, all of you.
You heard me.
Go.
But, Brother, don't you want
to keep practicing?
We're wasting our time, Rom.
We couldn't get
anywhere near Moogie
let alone rescue her.
I guess we're not cut out
to be heroes after all.
And to think,
just a few short days ago
I was sitting
on top of the world.
The King of Squill.
You should have been there,
Brother.
It was a very delicate
negotiation.
It could've gone either way,
but I took my time
picked my moment, and then...
went in for the kill.
It was beautiful to behold.
Brother...
I think we've been going
about this the wrong way.
We're not commandos.
We're negotiators.
We make deals.
That's what we're good at.
The Dominion has something
we want
so we need to find something
they want...
And then we make a trade!
That way,
everyone goes home happy.
Happy and alive.
Now, what do we have to trade?
Captain, I can't thank you
enough for all your help.
Don't thank me.
Thank Major Kira.
She's the one that convinced me
to talk to Starfleet
on your behalf.
Consider it payback, Quark
for rescuing me
from the Dominion.
Breaking you out
of the station's holding cell
is one thing.
What you're planning to do
is considerably more dangerous.
Every negotiation has
its share of danger, Captain.
If you say so.
I guess it's time for me
to pick up my prisoner.
Just be careful you don't
turn your back on him, Quark.
He's not to be trusted.
Neither am I.
Excuse me.
Ah!
Sorry.
This isn't a ship.
It's a closet.
If you don't like it here,
leave.
I'll go.
That way there'll be more room
for the rest of you.
Besides, this isn't
a rescue mission anymore.
It's a simple prisoner exchange.
I don't know
why Quark needs any of us.
Because he doesn't trust
the Dominion.
And neither do I.
Why would the Dominion
pick a deserted Cardassian
space station
to make the trade?
They didn't pick it, Quark did.
I've been there.
It's the same design
as Deep Space 9
so we know the layout.
Well, you have nothing
to worry about.
You'll have plenty of places
to run and hide.
Everyone, this is Keevan.
We're going to trade him
for Ishka.
Hi.
I'm Rom.
This is Nog.
That's Brunt...
Rom...
he doesn't care.
Truer words have
never been spoken.
I'll advise you all
to send final messages
to your loved ones
and make sure
your wills are in order.
Why?
Because the moment
we leave this station
you'll have signed
your death warrants.
Now if you don't mind
I'm going to take a nap.
All clear!
Are you sure?
Tricorder indicates no other
life-forms on the station.
All right.
Let's head for base camp.
"Base camp"?
He means the Infirmary.
It's right over there.
Come on. Let's move it.
On the double!
Well, what are you waiting for?
Two slips of latinum
for the first man
who makes it to the Infirmary.
I mean "base camp."
You don't pay your soldiers
to do their duty.
You do if they're Ferengi.
Great! Another closet.
We've chosen this spot
for a reason.
For one thing,
it's a confined area
with only two ways in or out...
this one,
and that one over there.
Secondly, it's near the airlock
which gives us
access to our ship
and third, it's on the Promenade
where the prisoner exchange
will take place.
Don't touch that.
Some of this medical equipment
is still functioning.
Anything for an upset stomach?
What you need is a new backbone.
Hey!
I'm a weapons dealer,
not a soldier.
Cousin!
Sir, may I suggest we set up
our defense perimeter?
Good idea.
How much is this
going to cost me?
Don't worry.
No charge.
Starfleet has really
corrupted you, hasn't it?
You could start by getting
the external sensors
back on line.
I want to know the minute
a Dominion ship
gets within ten million
kilometers of this station.
I'll set up
a transport jamming signal.
That way,
the Dominion won't be able
to beam our prisoner away
without our say-so.
We certainly wouldn't
want that to happen, would we?
You don't seem
to be too happy
at the prospect
of rejoining your people.
Believe me when I tell you
I have nothing
to be happy about.
Vorta are supposed
to commit suicide
when they're captured.
I failed to follow
that rather... harsh policy.
So they're going to execute you?
After what is surely going to be
a most unpleasant debriefing.
I'm sorry to hear about that,
but it's not my problem.
All I want is my Moogie back.
By the time the Dominion
is done with you
all you'll want...
is a quick... death.
Take him in the next room
and see that he stays there.
We'll post a guard
on him at all times.
Four hour shifts.
You heard him. Move.
Perhaps you can help me
clarify something.
What's the most vulnerable part
of a Jem'Hadar's body, hmm?
All right.
You have your orders.
Let's get to work.
My son the soldier.
They've ruined him.
What was that?
Who's screaming?
It's Gaila!
The Vorta... where is he?
I don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
You were guarding him!
He must have slipped away
while I was sleeping.
Sleeping?!
Who said you could sleep?
I couldn't help it.
I was tired.
I couldn't get any rest
on the ship.
The ship...
if Keevan gets away,
we're finished!
Ah!
Going someplace?
Apparently not.
I couldn't get
the impulse engines on line.
That's because I had Rom
disengage the induction matrix.
Then why did you
bother chasing me?
Because sometimes
my brother gets things wrong.
All right, everyone relax.
No harm done.
We still have our prisoner.
What's that?!
It's the alarm I set up.
It means a Dominion ship
is approaching.
To the Infirmary!
Let's go!
Now what?
Someone turned the alarm off.
Maybe it went off by itself.
Do you hear something?
Someone's out there.
One of us
should go check to make sure.
I nominate Quark.
Me?
I'll go.
Firing line take aim.
Anybody there?
You could say that.
I wonder what they're
doing out there.
Shh.
I don't hear anything.
Quiet.
Why are we hiding?
There are Jem'Hadar out there.
Of course they're out there.
We asked them to come.
He's right.
Everything's going
according to plan.
Now, all you have to do, Quark
is negotiate
the prisoner exchange.
Remember, be firm, strong.
But don't get them angry.
Good luck, Brother.
Say "Hi" to Moogie for me.
What if it's a trap?
Of course it's a trap.
They're not here to negotiate.
They're here to kill us all.
You think?
Don't listen to him.
He's just trying
to save his own neck.
I'm trying to save
all our necks.
Ferengi, show yourself.
We're here to trade.
Don't go out there.
We must get back to the ship.
Our only hope is to escape.
We're not going anywhere...
not without Moogie.
Right, Uncle?
Right.
Ferengi, I don't like
to be kept waiting.
I'm coming.
I'm coming!
And you two are coming with me.
I was afraid he was
going to say that.
Rom...
Moogie!
My boys.
I knew you'd come.
You look beautiful.
My lobes haven't been this firm
in over a century.
I guess that
makes all this worthwhile.
Don't you start with me, Quark.
What a touching
and heartfelt reunion.
I'm glad I was
here to witness it.
Now, where's Keevan?
I wish to conclude
this transaction.
All in good time
but first,
I need some assurances.
What kind of assurances?
Well, for one thing
I don't want any Jem'Hadar
soldiers on this station.
That would leave me
in a very vulnerable position.
One Vorta against six Ferengi.
If it makes you feel better,
these two can stay.
I feel safer already.
Now, where's Keevan?
Hold on, I'm not done yet.
Then, you're going to tell
your helmsman
to head back to Dominion
territory... warp nine.
That would leave me
stranded here.
For a few days.
I see
and by the time they return,
you'll be long gone.
That's the idea.
On the other hand,
I could have my Jem'Hadar
storm the Infirmary
and kill you all.
I like our plan better.
You attack the Infirmary
and Keevan will be
the first to die.
Keevan's fate
has already been sealed.
Maybe, but before he dies,
I'll bet you'll want to know
what Dominion secrets
he's revealed to the Federation.
He's got you there, Yelgrun.
Your people have
a reputation for cunning.
I see that it's well-earned.
Perhaps one day, the Ferengi
will take their place
as valued members
of the Dominion.
Anything's possible.
I will begin to evacuate
the Jem'Hadar at once.
We can exchange the prisoners
in, let's say, half an hour?
We'll be waiting.
One more thing.
How do we know
that's really Moogie
and not a changeling?
I think that uniform
is too tight on you, Nog.
It's cutting off circulation
to your brain.
Sounds like Moogie.
Only one way to find out.
Wait.
This should be interesting.
Ow!
Yeah. That's blood all right.
I knew it was Moogie.
Now let's see
if you're a changeling.
That's no way
to tell if he's a changeling.
You're right.
Give me that knife.
I don't think so.
Family...
you understand.
Not really.
I was cloned.
No parents?
That explains a lot.
No parents, no sweetheart.
No investment portfolio.
And no patience.
We'll meet back here
in one half hour.
Don't be late.
You heard him, Quark.
Rom, I'm counting on you.
Remember... Moogie loves you.
You should have
seen my brother.
He was brilliant.
In a half hour
we'll have Moogie back
and we can all go home.
Home... to the torrential rains
of Ferenginar.
You know what I miss most?
The rotting vegetation.
Yep.
And the dampness.
Oh, to stand once more
in those rivers of muck.
Oh, I only wish I
could be there with you.
I can't believe it.
We're actually going
to get the reward money.
50 bars of gold-pressed latinum.
50 bars?
You said the reward was 20.
That's what Rom said.
20.
He said 50.
I thought you said you
didn't care about latinum.
I don't! I just don't
like to be cheated.
Everyone calm down.
Calm down? When my dear cousin
is trying to cheat me?
I'm not trying to cheat anyone.
Then what about
the other 30 bars?!
There are no other 30 bars...
are there?
Uh... no, not really.
He's lying.
They're in it together.
You're not going to get
away with this, Quark!
I come here, risk my life,
and for what?!
You've had this coming
for a long time, Cousin!
Look out!
I hate Ferengi.
You idiot.
What are we going to do?
We can't have
a prisoner exchange
without a prisoner.
If they find out Keevan's dead
they're going to kill us.
Will you stop saying that?
Maybe, if we surrender,
they won't hurt us.
I have a better idea.
Let's sneak back to my ship
and try to escape.
It's a big station...
easy to get lost in.
If we hide,
maybe they won't find us.
No one's hiding
and no one's escaping
and no one's surrendering.
What's wrong with you people?
Have you forgotten
the Battle of Prexnak?
Who could forget
the most important battle
in Ferengi history?!
Ten Ferengi stood alone
against 273 Lytasians.
As I recall, all ten Ferengi
were slaughtered.
The point is
we Ferengi are just as tough
as anyone in the galaxy.
And this is our chance
to prove it...
once and for all.
Quark's right.
Let's do it for Ishka.
Let's do it
for the Grand Nagus.
for Ferengis everywhere!
Let's do it for equal shares
of 50 bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
It always comes down to profit
with you people, doesn't it?
We're Ferengi.
And that's why I love you!
50 bars it is...
minus my usual finder's fee.
Well, there's no doubt about it.
According to these readings,
this man is dead.
Thank you, Dr. Nog.
I just wanted to be sure.
I thought maybe
we could revive him,
but I guess not.
He's alive!
No, he isn't.
It's just the neural stimulator.
It caused a reflexive impulse
in his cerebellum.
I never knew you studied
medicine at the Academy.
I didn't,
but if you think about it
medicine isn't that different
from engineering.
It's all about
keeping things running
fixing broken parts.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Find me more neural stimulators!
It's time, Ferengi.
Bring out your prisoner.
Stall them, Uncle.
I'll try.
I've done as you asked.
The Jem'Hadar are on their way
back to Dominion territory.
We are alone on the station.
Wonderful.
Now bring out Keevan
and we can conclude
our business.
Keevan. Right. Absolutely.
I'm waiting.
He'll be right out.
But first...
my brother has to run
some sensor scans
to make sure the Jem'Hadar
have really left.
That is unnecessary.
The Jem'Hadar are gone.
Now bring me Keevan.
I will, in a few minutes.
No, not in a few minutes.
Now!
Or maybe you've changed
your mind
and you don't want
your mother back.
Kill her.
No!
Give them what they want, Quark.
I intend to.
Excellent.
As soon as my brother completes
his sensor scans.
And I thought the Breen
were annoying.
Very well.
Five minutes...
but I will not tolerate
any more delays.
Neither will I.
That goes for me, too.
You see, we're all in agreement.
Um...
one more thing.
Why am I not surprised?
The prisoner exchange...
I'd like for it to take place
outside Airlock 3.
What's wrong with the Promenade?
Nothing
except my ship is docked
at Airlock 3.
You understand.
Only too well
but I must say your lack
of trust saddens me.
Ah, well...
a sign of the times.
Nog, you have five minutes.
All right.
Here we go.
7,500 lots of hypicate futures?
The hypicate root
is very versatile.
It's used in certain medicines,
diffractive optics
and even some beauty supplies.
Here, feel
how smooth my head is.
Cream of hypicate.
I apply it twice a day.
You see, a diversified
financial portfolio
can mean greater profits
and healthier-looking skin.
Fascinating.
I'd love to hear more
but if your son
doesn't show up soon
I'm afraid I'm going
to have to kill you.
Yelgrun!
You ready?
I've been ready for hours.
On a count of three,
we release our prisoners.
Agreed?
Agreed.
One...
two...
three.
What have they done to him?
Straighten him out.
I'm trying.
Stop them!
Would you please turn him off?
I can't.
The transceiver is jammed.
Oh, Quark
the Grand Nagus is going
to be so proud of you.
I know I am.
Moogie...
What do we do with this one?
We'll take him with us.
He'll be our gift to Starfleet.
They gave us a Vorta,
we'll give them one.
Ferengi...
I know, I know... you hate us.
All right, you...
get moving!
This is the sloppiest,
most amateurish operation
I've ever seen.
If you ever do something
like this again
count me in.
You'll be the first one I call.
If I even think about doing
something like this again
shoot me.
So, Brother
how does it feel to be a...
hero?
You tell me.
It feels...
good?
You bet it does.