Captain's Log, Stardate 51408.6.
I've been aboard the Honshu
for two days now
and I still
haven't spoken to him
although the doctors
have assured me
that he's made a full recovery.
Maybe that's
what I'm afraid of.
Maybe I prefer to think of him
as a crazy man...
a broken man.
He'd be less dangerous that way.
As terrible as it sounds
there's a part of me
that wishes he were dead
but that's a thought unworthy
of a Starfleet Officer.
He lost an empire,
he lost his daughter
and he nearly lost his mind.
Whatever his crimes
isn't that enough punishment
for one lifetime?
I heard you were aboard.
I was wondering
if you'd make an appearance.
How are you?
Better.
The doctors tell me
I've made a remarkable recovery.
They told me the same thing.
Good.
I'd hate to think
they were patronizing me.
So I'm a war criminal.
In the Federation, you're
innocent till proven guilty.
So I'm told.
Do you believe I'm guilty,
Benjamin?
I haven't seen...
all of the charges.
It's not like you to equivocate.
I'm trying to be fair.
You won't be tried
until the war is over.
Your appearance
before the special jury
is just a formality.
And you'll be testifying
for the prosecution.
I will tell them what I know.
Care to elaborate?
Not really.
I see.
I never got a chance to tell you
how sorry I am about Ziyal.
Do I detect the fine hand
of Dr. Cox at work once again?
I told him I wanted
to offer my condolences.
I'm sorry.
The good doctor encourages me
to talk about Ziyal
whenever possible
since it was her...
death
that brought on
my momentary instability.
I shouldn't be so suspicious.
It's all right.
Well...
we should be arriving
at Starbase 621
by noon tomorrow.
I will see you
at the arraignment.
Benjamin...
about my daughter...
you and Major Kira
took care of her
for almost a year.
I wanted to thank you
for that.
It was very generous.
Ziyal...
was a very special young woman.
It was a pleasure
to have her with us
even if it was
only a short time.
A short time
is all she ever had.
Is there anything
I can get for you?
Hmm.
A bottle of kanar
and an Orion slave girl
would be nice.
I'll see what I can do.
Battle stations.
Damage control teams
report to Level 5-J.
It's confirmed.
USS Honshu was destroyed
this morning at 1030 hours
by an attack wing
of Cardassian destroyers.
Starfleet has picked up
the distress beacons
from three escape pods
and one shuttlecraft
so there are survivors.
The signals
are coming from this area.
The last reported position
of the Honshu was here
which means there could
be survivors in any of these
adjacent star systems.
That's a pretty large area.
How many ships
in the search party?
Two... the Constellation
and the Defiant.
Two? It could take days.
With all the Dominion activity
along the border
it's all Starfleet
can spare at the moment
and, the Defiant has
another appointment.
In 52 hours
you need to be at this
rendezvous point
outside the Badlands.
You are the escort
for a Federation troop convoy.
It will take 12 hours
just to arrive
at the coordinates
where the Honshu was destroyed.
And 12 more
to reach the Badlands, I know,
but this convoy
is completely unprotected.
They've been using
the plasma fields
in the Badlands
to hide their movements
and when they emerge, they're
helpless without the Defiant.
Can't they delay the convoy?
I mean, if Captain
Sisko is still alive
we have to give him
every chance.
I raised
the same objection myself
and the orders still stand.
Now, every minute spent
arguing here is one less minute
spent searching for the Captain.
Prepare
for immediate departure.
Worf...
there are over 30,000
Federation troops
in that convoy.
You have 52 hours,
not one second longer.
Understood?
Understood.
Defiant.
Benjamin, can you hear me?
Dukat?
Yes.
Everything's all right
but don't try
to move too quickly.
The left side of your body
is covered with plasma burns.
We were in the brig
and the ship went to Red Alert.
We were attacked
by a wing of Cardassian
ships, ironically.
I was headed to Engineering.
Well, you didn't get very far.
A plasma conduit exploded
before you got 15 meters
down the corridor.
That's where Lieutenant
McConnell and I found you
when the order came
to abandon ship.
Where's McConnell?
Dead.
A piece of shrapnel
hit him in the head
just as we were carrying
you into the shuttle.
Any other survivors?
I saw a few escape pods
leaving the ship
just before it exploded
but I had my hands full
just trying to keep
us in one piece.
The engines were damaged
from the shock waves
and I set us down here
wherever "here" is.
But that shuttle's
never going
to reach orbit again.
The shuttle's distress
beacon was damaged...
but I think
I managed to repair it.
So now all we have to do
is wait for someone to pick up
our signal.
Whose signal
are you transmitting...
Starfleet or
the Dominion, hmm?
It's a general distress call,
Benjamin.
Whoever gets here first
will find one comrade-in-arms...
and one prisoner.
That's fair, isn't it?
Fair enough.
Did you do this?
You shattered most
of the bones in your arm.
There was a bone regenerator
in the medkit
but I'm afraid
I'm not much of a doctor
so I just put on the cast.
You did plenty.
Thank you.
We have enough field rations
to last us a few weeks,
but I'd feel
better, if I could locate
another source
of food and water.
The surface is inhospitable,
to say the least
but I did manage to find
some firewood and kindling
so there's a good chance
there's edible vegetation
out there...
I just have to find it.
You could have left me behind.
Why didn't you?
I didn't want to.
I'll be back within the hour.
What are you planning
to do with him?
The Captain and I have
a lot to talk about.
Such as?
It's of a personal nature.
I see.
You're going
to share your feelings
of loneliness and sorrow
with your long-time adversary.
Dr. Cox would be so proud.
Go away.
You should kill him now
while you still can.
That won't be necessary.
He's in no condition
to challenge me.
I can afford to be patient.
You should kill him.
I don't care for your tone!
Spare me your endless posturing.
You're lucky
I speak to you at all
after that pathetic display
back at the hospital.
That's enough.
Oh, I see.
It's a sensitive topic.
I wonder what Captain
Sisko would think
if he'd seen you
curled up in a ball
crying yourself to sleep
every night.
Stop it!
I doubt he'd still have
the same respect for you
if he'd heard you screaming
and screaming and screaming
like a madman
till the nurses came
and the doctors
had to sedate you.
No!
Is that breakfast?
Possibly.
Good morning.
Morning.
What's it like outside?
Oh, the wind has died down
and the temperature
has gone up 20 degrees.
I rather like it
but I think you'll
be more comfortable
in here where it's cooler.
Too much.
I'm doing the cooking here,
thank you.
Pardon me.
You're not the only officer
who learned how to cook,
you know.
How are you feeling?
A little better.
Good.
After last night
I was beginning to get worried.
Last night?
You don't remember?
Now that you mention it,
I remember waking up
and I was feeling
a little dizzy.
You had a bout of nausea.
Not exactly a little bout.
Oh. I'm sorry.
That's all right.
I've had to clean up
a lot worse in my time.
Once, when I was
a newly minted glinn
on the Kornaire
I had to help
clean out a compartment
where three men had gone through
an explosive decompression.
I didn't sleep for a week
after that.
Let's change the subject.
The Emissary has spoken.
Oh, come on, Benjamin.
Have a sense of humor
about all this.
I'm not in much
of a joking mood.
Well, that's a shame,
because there's so much
to laugh about.
You don't see it, do you?
Benjamin, just a few hours ago
I was a prisoner
on my way to trial
and you were my dear old friend
come to visit me in my cell.
Now look at us.
I'm free, and you're a prisoner
of your own battered body
and there's a good chance
we'll be rescued
by the Dominion.
You've got to laugh
at a universe
that allows such radical shifts
in fortune, Benjamin.
I will laugh when
a Federation starship arrives
and puts you back in a cell.
Whatever you say.
What?
Nothing.
It's probably just the wind.
How is it?
Needs salt.
There's probably some
in one of the ration packs.
You know... we didn't get
much of a chance
to catch up before the attack.
How is everybody
on what I'm sure
you're once again calling
Deep Space 9?
Odo and... Kira?
Quark?
They're all fine.
And, no, they don't miss you.
Perhaps not.
They never really did
give me much of a chance.
They were too busy
plotting my downfall.
Pepper.
If you only want me to tell you
what you want to hear,
just say so.
Well, I hope
they at least told you
that my policies
toward the Bajorans
were most generous this time.
They told me Weyoun didn't
give you much of a choice.
Major Kira knows full well
I made every effort
to heal the wounds
between Cardassia and Bajor.
Since the very beginning
it was my intention to rectify
the mistakes of the past
and begin a new chapter
in our relations.
Are you going
to put that in my soup?
Oh.
Well?
Better.
You're not going to give me
the benefit of the doubt
are you, Benjamin?
Do you really care what I think?
Don't you care what your
old friends think of you?
Dukat, we're not old friends.
You saved my life
and I'm grateful
but that's as far as it goes.
You keep hearing something.
Are you sure
there's nothing out there?
It's just the wind.
I'm certain.
But I'm going to double-check,
just to make sure.
No.
I won't do it... not yet.
You're wasting time.
It's my time to waste, Damar.
Remember your place.
I mean no disrespect...
you know that... but without you
the war will be lost
and Cardassia will lie in ruins.
Don't let this one man
stand in the way
of your final triumph.
I have to know
that he respects me.
I think I've earned it.
Of course you have.
He's just trying
to deny you the satisfaction
of hearing him say it.
You know in your heart
he secretly admires you.
Isn't that enough?
Kill him and be done with it.
Think of it...
the leader of Cardassia
bringing the dead body
of the Emissary back
to the Bajoran people.
They'll take it as a sign
that the Prophets
have abandoned them.
The Shakaar government
will be overthrown
and the Federation position
on Terok Nor
will become untenable.
Very tempting thought.
You've made
some good points, Damar
but there will be time
enough for all of that later.
It's all right.
I know you have
my best interests at heart.
I wanted to get
some water out of the kit.
Oh.
Here.
Thanks.
Oh...
Anything out there?
Hmm?
Uh, no. No.
Some rocks slid down the cliff.
I think something's wrong
with the com system.
Oh?
It was beeping a second ago.
It might need recalibrating.
I'll check.
Well...
everything's fine.
The unit's still on line.
If you open up the casing
you'll be able to run
a full diagnostic.
Better safe than sorry.
You're right.
Ah...
Nothing to worry about.
It's working fine.
That's all I wanted to know.
Ship's Log, supplemental.
We have picked up a total
of 12 Honshu survivors so far
but there is still
no sign of Captain Sisko.
We have less than 12 hours
before we must
abandon the search.
Damn.
Commander, I'm picking up
a distress signal.
Good evening.
Pleasant dreams, I hope.
I don't remember.
Is it still dark out?
I do apologize for bringing you
to such a gloomy latitude.
The nights seem to last 18 hours
the days less than five.
Sit up.
Well, looks like you're
planning a long stay.
Oh, no, not at all.
Someone's bound to pick up
our signal any time now
but I see no reason
why we shouldn't be comfortable
in the meantime.
How's that?
That's just fine, thank you.
Good.
Ahh!
Much better, hmm?
You know
when I was out there
in the shuttle just now
it occurred to me
that the Bajorans
would be very confused
if they could see us here
sharing the same food,
the same hardships.
What do you think they would say
if they knew
the Emissary of the Prophets
and the evil Gul Dukat
were sitting here, together
getting along
just like the two old friends
that they really are?
Oh...
I... forgot.
You don't think of me
as your old friend
do you, Benjamin?
It's all right.
There's no one here.
Just the two of us.
No one to impress.
No one to judge what you say.
We can be honest
with each other.
So tell me...
what do you really think of me?
I'll tell you what I think.
I think you're
an evil, sadistic man
who should have been tried
as a war criminal years ago...
put up against a wall and shot.
You probably agree
with Major Kira
don't you, Benjamin?
I am the former Prefect
of Bajor...
an evil man
who sent thousands of Bajorans
to their deaths
to satisfy his own
sadistic desires, hmm?
Of course, he agrees with me
and it was millions.
I don't think there's any point
in discussing this.
I do.
My name and reputation
have been slandered and twisted
ever since the end
of the occupation of Bajor.
I have been vilified...
by ignorant, small-minded people
throughout the Quadrant
for the past six years.
I just want to know
if you're one of them, Benjamin.
I wasn't there
during the occupation.
I didn't see all the things
you had to struggle with
day after day.
I don't think
I can pass judgment.
He just doesn't
want to anger you.
He really thinks
you're a vicious
cold-blooded killer,
Dukat, and so do I.
I don't care what you think,
so I suggest
you keep your opinions
to yourself.
I don't think
you're being entirely honest
with me, Benjamin.
You're not a man who hesitates
to make snap judgments
when the situation calls for it.
It's one of the signs
of a good commander.
Now, I'm asking
for your opinion of me
and I'd find it hard to believe
you don't have one.
All right.
I think you're right.
You have been judged unfairly.
I've judged you unfairly
but I think you probably had
good reasons
for everything you did on Bajor.
Yes.
Yes. That's it, exactly.
I had good reasons.
Some of the harsher actions
I took
were forced on me
by Central Command.
I wanted to use
entirely different tactics
with the Bajorans.
I wanted to rule
with a softer hand
but my superiors
didn't see it that way.
You were a soldier, and you
had to carry out your orders.
Precisely.
You are such a fool!
Leave us alone!
This doesn't concern you!
He's patronizing you.
"You were a soldier
and you had to carry out
your orders."
He doesn't believe
that lame excuse
any more than I do.
This is growing tiresome.
Dukat?
Dukat!
I thought you wanted
to talk to me.
Yes!
But Nerys won't
leave well enough alone.
She's always interfering,
always trying to upset me!
Maybe we should
just ignore her.
Let's pretend that the Major's
not even here.
I'm picking up two humanoid
life-forms on the surface.
Bridge to Transporter Room.
There's no reason to get upset.
We're just talking.
Two old soldiers
talking around the campfire.
I'm going to enjoy
watching this.
He's going to beat you, Dukat.
He's going to escape
and go back to DS9
and his friends
and we're all going
to have a good, long laugh
at your expense.
Enough!
I've locked onto them.
Transporter Room to Bridge.
We have the survivors on board.
Two women...
an Ensign and a Lieutenant.
Dr. Bashir is checking them now.
That must have been
very uncomfortable, Benjamin.
Look at that.
One of the tines is missing.
How did that happen?
Did you break it off?
But why would you want
a small, thin piece of met...
Unless you needed a tool.
I see you've been busy.
A little repair work
while I was gone.
Very thoughtful.
Worf!
What is it?
I thought I picked up
another distress signal
but now it's gone.
You know, Benjamin
I thought we had established
a level of trust between us
but I was wrong.
If there's one thing
I can't abide, it's betrayal.
Our rescue efforts
have been delayed.
If we could just have
a few more hours.
The troop convoy
will be completely
unprotected...
when they... the plasma...
...strict radio silence.
...they can acknowledge
our signal
even if...
...sorry, Worf,
but you're going to have...
your search and...
I'm sorry, Captain.
There's some kind
of subspace interference
between us and the station.
I'll keep trying.
I couldn't understand
a word Kira said.
Too much interference.
It looks to me
like we're on our own.
I could understand
what she was trying to say.
What about you, Chief?
Did you understand?
No, I couldn't understand
a word.
Well, it doesn't really matter
what we think.
Commander Worf is Captain here.
We all know
what Major Kira's orders were.
It would dishonorable
to ignore them.
You will forgive me...
if I don't consider
your honor...
to be worth
Captain Sisko's life.
You may leave the Bridge,
Doctor.
Helm.
Set a course
for the third planet.
Aye, Captain.
You brought it
on yourself, you know.
Just like all your victims.
All my victims.
It always comes back
to that, doesn't it?
All my crimes.
I'm such a monster
such an evil man.
Behold... Benjamin Sisko...
supreme arbiter of right
and wrong in the universe...
a man of such high
moral caliber
that he can sit in judgment
on all the rest of us.
What the hell do you want
from me?!
My approval?
Is that what this is all about?
You want me to give you
my permission
to cause more suffering
and death?
Well, if that's
what you're after
you might as well
pull out that phaser
and end this right now
because I will never
give it to you!
Good!
Good. I like this.
No more pretense.
No games.
Just you, me and the truth.
What do you know
about the truth?
You bend the truth
into whatever shape suits you.
Judge Sisko hands down
another ruling.
But where's his evidence?
All right.
You really want to do this?
Here? Now?
Yes!
Okay.
Okay. Let's do it!
You were Prefect of Bajor
during the occupation.
True or false?
True.
And you were responsible
for everything
that happened
under your command.
True or false?
True.
So that means
that you are responsible
for the murder
of over five million Bajorans
on your watch.
True or false?!
False. I tried to save lives
during my administration.
Evidence?!
Evidence!
He wants evidence.
By the time I became Prefect
the occupation had been going on
for almost 40 years
but the planet
still wasn't ready
for full-scale colonization.
Central Command
wanted the situation resolved
and they didn't care
how it was done.
I was convinced
that a gentler hand
was required to deal
with the Bajorans.
It was a noble,
if misguided vision.
So in my first official
act as Prefect
I ordered
all labor camp commanders
to reduce their output quotas
by 50 percent.
Then I reorganized
the camps themselves.
Child labor was abolished.
Medical care was improved.
Food rations were increased.
At the end of one month
of my administration
the death rate had dropped
by 20 percent.
Now, how did the Bajorans
react to all this?
On my one-month anniversary
they blew up
an orbital dry dock...
killing over 200 Cardassian
soldiers and workers.
We didn't want a reconciliation.
We wanted to destroy you.
So I had to order a response.
But even then,
it was a carefully-tempered one.
I ordered 200 suspected members
of the resistance
rounded up and executed.
200 lives for 200 lives.
That's justice, not malevolence.
Justice.
The Dominion would have
never been so generous.
But did I give up
my efforts to reach out
to the Bajorans?
No. I tried again
and what did I get
for my troubles?
An assassination attempt...
on my own station.
Another round of executions
followed...
once again, courtesy
of the Bajoran resistance.
We never wanted peace.
We hated you.
We hated all of you.
On and on it went
year after blood-soaked year.
Time and again,
I would reach out
with an open hand
of friendship
and time and again
they would slap it away.
The Bajorans understand
a clenched fist
not an open hand.
Being reasonable
only made us bolder.
The Dominion would have killed
every man, woman and child
on Bajor long ago.
I hope you're listening
to all this.
Oh, believe me...
you have my undivided attention.
Now, let me get this straight.
You're not responsible
for what happened
during the occupation
the Bajorans are, hmm?
Yes. Yes!
Exactly.
So, why do you
think they didn't
appreciate this rare opportunity
you were offering them, hmm?
Oh, because...
they were blind, ignorant fools.
If only they had
cooperated with us
we could have turned
their world into a paradise.
From the moment
we arrived on Bajor
it was clear
that we were the superior race
but they couldn't accept that.
They wanted
to be treated as equals
when they most certainly
were not.
Militarily, technologically,
culturally...
we were almost a century
ahead of them in every way.
We did not choose to be
the superior race.
Fate handed us that role
and it would have been
so much easier on everyone
if the Bajorans had simply
accepted their role.
But, no...
day after day
they clustered in their temples
and prayed for deliverance
and night after night,
they planted bombs
outside of our homes.
Pride...
stubborn, unyielding pride.
From the servant girl
that cleaned my quarters
to the condemned man
toiling in a labor camp
to the terrorist
skulking through the hills
of Dahkur Province...
they all wore their pride
like some...
twisted badge of honor.
And you hated them for it.
Of course I hated them!
I hated everything about them!
Their superstitions
and their cries for sympathy
their treachery and their lies
their smug superiority
and their stiff-necked obstinacy
their earrings and their
broken, wrinkled noses.
You should have killed them all,
hmm?
Yes! Yes!
That's right, isn't it?!
I knew it.
I've always known it.
I should have killed
every last one of them.
I should have turned their
planet into a graveyard
the likes of which
the galaxy had never seen!
I should have killed them all.
And that is why...
you're not an evil man.
Do it!
I'm so glad
we had this time together,
Benjamin
because we won't be seeing
each other for a while.
I have unfinished business
on Bajor.
They thought I was their enemy.
They don't know what it is
to be my enemy, but they will.
From this day forward,
Bajor is dead!
All of Bajor!
And this time
even their Emissary
won't be able to save them!
It's time.
Plot a course out of the system.
Full impulse.
Once we've cleared
the outer planets
head for the rendezvous
coordinates... maximum warp.
Course laid in.
Engaging impulse engines.
Captain,
I'm picking up a signal.
It's from Gul Dukat.
Ship's Log, Stardate 51413.6.
We have rescued Captain Sisko
but we did not have time
to locate Gul Dukat's shuttle.
We are now en route
to our rendezvous
with the troop convoy
near the Badlands
and the Captain
is recovering in Sick Bay.
Benjamin?
I've notified Starfleet
of Dukat's last known position.
They'll find him.
No, they won't.
You know, old man
sometimes life seems
so complicated...
nothing is truly good
or truly evil.
Everything seems to be
a shade of gray.
And then, you spend some time
with a man like Dukat
and you realize that there is
such a thing as truly evil.
To realize that is one thing.
To do something about it
is another.
So, what are you going to do?
I'll tell you
what I'm not going to do.
I'm not going
to let him destroy Bajor.
I fear no evil.
From now on
it's him...
or me.