Morn, if you're not too busy,
I'd appreciate it if you did something
about that shipment of Livanian beets
you have sitting in Cargo Bay 3.
It's been there for over two weeks.
It's starting to rot.
Morn!
QUARK: It's a hologram.
Morn's been away on business
for the last two weeks.
You're slipping, Odo.
You should've caught on a lot sooner.
You replaced Morn with a hologram? Why?
-Evening.
-Hello, Morn.
QUARK: That's why.
People love him. He's like a mascot.
Everyone who comes in here
expects to see him
and if they don't,
it doesn't feel like home to them.
And that's not good for business.
The last time he went away,
my sales dropped almost five percent.
Oh.
Why doesn't it talk?
Do you have any idea how much
an interactive holo-projector costs?
Besides, it's a relief
not to have to listen to him go on.
You know Morn, he never shuts up.
I'd trade this for the real thing any day.
I'm sure Morn would be very touched
to hear you say that.
( gasping ) Morn!
No, it's just a hologram.
You look like you saw a ghost.
Turn it off.
Why?
We just got word. Morn's cargo ship
was caught in an ion storm.
Is he all right?
Was he rescued?
He's dead.
-Did you bring anything?
-Hmm?
To the memorial service?
I didn't know I was supposed to.
Well, it's a Lurian custom to bring gifts
of food and drink for the deceased
so they have something
to sustain them in the afterlife.
Oh. Well, maybe I can get something
in Quark's.
I hate to think
of the big fella going without.
Morn was an excellent sparring partner.
I will miss our weekly
combat in the holosuites.
I can't believe he's really gone.
I did not realize
he was such a close friend.
Well, I used to have
a little crush on him.
Morn?
Well, it was before we met.
Besides, he wasn't interested.
What do you mean he wasn't interested?
DAX: Oh, forget I mentioned it.
Is that a bottle opener?
Hmm. For Morn.
I thought it might come in handy.
-Very thoughtful.
-( chuckles )
This is unbelievable.
Look at all these people.
If you see anyone empty-handed
sell them a bottle of Yridian ale.
Tell them it was Morn's favorite.
Very kind of you to do this, Quark.
I'm sure Morn would've appreciated it.
It's the least I could do.
I'll miss him.
Sorry.
Can I get you anything?
I don't ordinarily imbibe
on the job, but... maybe a Yridian ale.
It was Morn's favorite.
Oh.
Well, perfect.
What are you looking at?
Your respect for the dead is heartwarming.
I'll have you know
Morn died without paying
this month's bar tab.
Oh, how inconsiderate of him.
We're talking about a lot of money.
The man had quite an appetite.
You know he had two stomachs to fill.
Ever watch him eat?
It was a beautiful thing.
Well, sometimes you don't truly
appreciate what you have until it's gone.
It's nice to know you're so worried
about my welfare.
You should be worried, too.
Now that your mascot's gone,
business will suffer.
We'll see. You might be surprised.
-Jadzia.
-Can we please drop this?
QUARK: Everyone, thank you all for coming.
It means a great deal to me
to see so many people cared
about Morn as much as I did.
I'll never forget
the first time he walked in here
and sat down on that very stool.
It must've been... almost ten years ago.
He still had his hair then.
I thought he was just another
customer passing through.
Little did I know...
he'd become such an important figure
in my life... in all our lives.
Morn was always someone
we could count on for a cheerful smile,
and an entertaining story.
Some of you might be thinking
this place won't be the same without him.
And it won't.
But this was his home.
And wherever he is,
I'm sure he'd want to know
that his favorite bar still echoed
with the laughter of his dear friends.
This was his chair.
And I think the greatest tribute
we could ever pay him
would be to make sure
that it is never empty.
Keep it warm... for Morn.
Every now and then,
Quark really surprises me.
Me, too.
Excuse me, Quark.
Not now.
I'm sorry to intrude,
but I thought you should know.
I unsealed Morn's will.
He left everything to you.
Me? He left everything to me?
That's right.
Morn...
dear, sweet Morn.
Oh...
The poor fool actually believed
you cared about him.
I did.
I was up for hours
last night thinking about him.
Calculating his net worth, no doubt.
We spent a lot of time together, Odo.
We were obviously a lot closer
than I ever realized.
His financial records.
Is this some kind of joke?
What do you mean?
According to this, he was broke.
( sarcastically ) No.
How can that be?
He paid his bar bill
at the end of every month.
That kind of money
must have come from somewhere.
Well, he did have his shipping business.
Maybe all his assets
are tied up in inventory.
Of course. Inventory.
I'll unload everything,
and use the profits to...
-Oh, what's that smell?
-Your inheritance.
Livanian beets. Very ripe.
What's in the rest of these?
More beets.
That's it? That's all he had?
I'm afraid so.
( gasps )
Except for the contents of his quarters.
Maybe he spent all his money
-on furnishings and works of art.
-Objets d'art.
Of course.
Objets d'art. Of course.
I'll hold an auction.
People will pay a premium
to own something that used to be Morn's.
Are you sure these are the right quarters?
I'm sure.
Figures.
What's that?
That, I believe, is a matador.
No. That.
ODO: That's Morn's bed.
Morn slept in...
-mud? -Hmm.
I'm told it's excellent for the skin.
Thanks, Morn.
Just what I always wanted.
( gasping )
What are you doing in my mud?
Oh, I... I couldn't resist.
Morny and I had so many happy times here,
I just... I had to slip in.
I'm sorry if I startled you.
I heard you coming in
and I thought I'd better hide.
Who are you?
Um...
Larell.
Morn's wife. Well, ex-wife.
Morn was married?
To you?
For two wonderful years.
You must be Quark.
Morny and I kept in touch
after we were separated.
He talked about you all the time.
That's nice.
He told me that if anything
ever happened to him,
he wanted you to have everything
that was ever his.
Everything?
Everything.
Well, I'm glad you came by,
because Morny didn't leave
me much of anything else.
Why, I find that hard to believe.
( laughs )
I'm as disappointed as you are.
I happen to know
that he had quite
a substantial retirement fund,
one that could make two people
very comfortable.
If you're partial to mud,
it's comfortable, all right.
I'm talking about the thousand bricks
of gold-pressed latinum
that he won in the Lissepian Lottery.
A thousand bricks?
Mm-hmm. Now that he's gone, it's all ours.
( vacuum slurping )
What are you doing?
What do you think?
I'm looking for the latinum.
You must know where he kept it.
I didn't even know it existed
until you told me.
Well, I'm sure it's somewhere
on the station.
How do we know he didn't spend it already?
I told you, it was for his retirement.
Poor Morn.
He never got a chance to enjoy it.
But that doesn't mean we can't.
I know what you're doing.
What am I doing?
Just so we're clear...
the latinum's mine.
He may have left everything to you,
but I was his wife.
I could contest the will,
and tie you up in court for years.
Maybe.
But there's no reason
it has to come to that.
After all, a thousand bricks is plenty
for both of us.
It is a lot of money.
And as soon as we find it,
we'll take a nice long vacation together.
Morn would have wanted it that way.
Of course, he would have.
The latinum's not on the station.
I looked everywhere. Evade.
I even had my brother scan for it
with the internal sensors.
Well, at least you have the painting.
Oh, forget the painting.
I want that latinum.
If you think it'll make you happy.
Confront.
Believe me, it will.
This is the break I've been waiting for,
and it's been a long time in coming.
I want Morn's money. I need Morn's money.
I deserve Morn's money.
Your move.
Beautiful, isn't it?
And the way it picks up the light.
I wonder who came up with the idea
of suspending liquid latinum
inside worthless bits of gold?
Probably someone who got
tired of making change
with an eyedropper.
Are you going to play or not?
Where do you think Morn put it all?
If you find it, are you really
going to share it with this woman?
I agreed to pay her ten percent
so she wouldn't tie me up in court.
That's 100 bricks.
What could I do?
Retreat.
I don't know, but there's something
I don't like about this whole thing.
I don't trust this woman.
Neither do I, but... that doesn't mean
I'm going to keep her away from my lobes.
Just keep your eyes open.
Don't be fooled by a pretty face.
Not me.
Of course not. Acquire.
Oh...
What a pleasant surprise.
Computer, lights.
Tell me... you like surprises, Quark?
Only pleasant ones.
I like to think I'm pleasant.
-You think I'm pleasant?
-Absolutely.
Then I guess this qualifies
as a pleasant surprise.
What are you doing in my quarters?
Waiting for you.
My brother and I were business
associates of Morn's.
If you've come for the memorial service,
it was yesterday.
Really? Was it nice?
It was lovely.
I understand you inherited Morn's estate.
That's right.
We're business associates of Morn's.
Your brother mentioned that.
He... borrowed some money from us,
and we'd like the estate
to repay the loan.
Uh-huh.
How much money are we talking about?
Oh...
One thousand bricks
of gold-pressed latinum.
I had a feeling
you were going to say that.
I need to see documentation
regarding this loan.
We shook hands.
We trusted Morn.
And I'm sure he'd want you...
to honor his word.
I'm sure he would,
but you have to understand,
Morn's assets are all tied up
in various enterprises.
I hope you're not saying
you don't have the money.
That wouldn't be good.
Uh... all I meant was it'll take me
a little while to get it.
-So you do know where it is.
-QUARK: Of course.
You're not the first creditors
to make a claim against his estate.
We're not?
Morn was expanding his business interests
when he died.
His resources were stretched
somewhat thin.
As a result, the claims against the estate
are greater than the assets.
Obviously, you can't expect
full repayment.
What can we expect?
A percentage.
What sort of percentage?
Twenty.
We can't accept less than 80.
I'll make it 30,
and I'll throw in a shipment
of Livanian beets.
I don't like beets.
We'll take 70.
Forty.
And because I can see
you both have fine taste,
I'm willing to part with this.
One of Morn's most treasured possessions.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Very nice.
We can't take less than 60.
Forty's the best I can do.
-Fifty.
-Sorry.
Fifty it is.
I'm glad we could come
to an understanding.
Me, too.
( laughs )
We'll be watching you, Quark.
Don't try anything.
Me? Don't be ridiculous.
What do we have here?
Computer, what is this?
COMPUTER: A claim slip
for Storage Locker 137,
located in the Station Assay Office.
A storage locker!
Thank you, computer.
You've been very helpful.
Morn, wherever you are, I love you!
What do you mean
I have to open it in here?
Regulations, the contents
of a deceased person's storage locker
have to be inspected by station security.
There's no such regulation.
You just want to know what's inside.
You are so transparent.
I can't wait to see your face
when your deputies wheel
in my thousand bricks of latinum.
Ah, here we are. Thank you.
That can't be it.
Storage Locker 137.
Well... sometimes,
good things come in small packages.
Hmm...
will that be enough
to cover Morn's bar tab?
It's covered.
There's more where this came from.
What makes you say that?
Take a look.
On the bottom.
Recognize Morn's handwriting?
"The rest is in the Bank of Bolias."
Account number C-J-5-74-36.
Hmph.
This wasn't in Morn's financial record.
Who cares?
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm going to contact the bank
and let them know Morn's legal heir
would like his latinum delivered
as soon as possible.
Larell...
I've been looking all over for you.
I'm a busy man.
Not too busy to look
for a certain something, I hope.
Actually I haven't had much
luck with that.
Sounds like you need a little motivation.
Oh...
I'm motivated, believe me.
It's just that it's going to take some
time to locate, that's all.
Mm-hmm.
Um... I have an idea.
Why don't you go back
to wherever you come from,
and I'll contact you as soon as I find it?
I think I'd rather wait here... with you.
Oh...
this is not a good time for oo-mox.
Why? Don't you like it?
Uh, it's not that. It's just that...
the sooner I find
that certain something...
Mmm...
the sooner we can take
our little trip together.
Mm, you're so diligent.
Most men don't know
how to defer gratification.
You don't make it easy.
Mm.
Good morning.
( drumming on doors )
Level 17.
( sighs )
You're good.
But... I'm the only one
the bank's going to give the money to.
Yeah.
C-J-5-74-36.
C-J-5-74... uh...
This is my stop.
What's your hurry?
My brother has something
he wants to say to you.
I'm sorry.
About the painting.
He feels terrible.
No hard feelings.
That's nice of you
to be so forgiving, Quark.
Don't mention it.
-My brother has a nasty temper.
-I get upset.
It comes out when things don't go our way.
I noticed. That's why I'm hoping
things start to go our way soon.
Do you understand what I'm saying, Quark?
I think I do, yes.
I don't like to get upset.
Don't worry.
Things are going to go your way soon.
That's good to hear.
I'll keep in touch.
I really am sorry about the painting.
C-J-5-74-36. C-J-5-74-36.
Bank of Bolias.
HAIN: Making a withdrawal, Quark?
Let me guess.
A thousand bricks of gold-pressed latinum.
Put your hands on your head.
Turn around.
All right, how much do you want?
And don't ask for the full 1,000 bricks.
I already gave away more than half of it.
Attempted bribery. That should add
a few years to your sentence.
-What are you talking about?
-Let's go.
Go? Wait, who are you?
Lurian Security. I have a signed
extradition order for your arrest.
-Oh.
-As soon as your station's
security chief approves it...
we'll be on our way.
What did I do? What's the charge?
Conspiracy to intercept
government property.
Government property?
1,000 bricks of gold-pressed latinum.
Wait a minute.
Morn won that latinum
in the Lissepian Lottery.
He didn't?
It was his bequest
from the Royal Family of Luria.
Oh...
Why would the Royal Family of Luria
give Morn that kind of money?
He was the crown prince.
Morn was a prince?
You didn't know?
That's what I'm saying.
-Morn was a prince.
-Yes.
But he renounced the throne
when he came of age.
Well, I always knew he was an idiot.
His family bequeathed him the latinum
when he abdicated.
But now that he's deceased,
it's legally theirs again.
Uh-uh.
He left it to me.
That will has already been nullified.
He signed an agreement to return
the latinum in the event of his death.
Oh.
Do me a favor. Don't tell his ex-wife.
I'm going to need a little oo-mox later.
His ex-wife?
Larell.
She's here?
Mm-hmm. I just saw her.
-Is something wrong?
-Quiet!
Let me think.
Listen and listen carefully.
Larell has been trying
to get her hands on the prince's
latinum for years.
She's tried blackmail, extortion.
I wouldn't be surprised
if she was behind his death.
She's always been nice to me.
The Royal Family would like nothing better
than to see her behind bars.
If you help me apprehend her,
there'll be a substantial reward.
What do I have to do?
When are you going to see her again?
She'll turn up sooner or later.
If not her, then those two brothers.
Brothers?
They said they
were Morn's business partners.
They claimed he owed them money.
Something tells me
they were not exactly aboveboard.
Whoever these brothers are I promise you,
I won't let them get
between the Royal Family and its latinum.
And I won't let anything get between me
and my reward.
Do we have an understanding?
-Uh-huh.
-If I'm going to put these people away
I have to catch them trying
to get their hands on the latinum.
Call the bank.
Tell them to deliver it here.
Then what?
You stay out of sight
and leave the rest to me.
What are you up to?
Trying to fix this optronic relay.
Wouldn't you be better
off working in a lab?
I'm keeping Morn's chair warm.
Ah.
Good man.
Where's Quark?
I'm in the mood
for one of his famous Til'amin froths.
You'll have to settle for something else.
He's in the back,
and from what Broik says,
he's not coming out.
Sounds like he's taking
Morn's death pretty hard.
Uh-huh. He loved the guy.
Well, I better go test this.
I'll take over.
Oh, good man.
Anybody here?
What a surprise.
You got to help me, Quark.
Someone's following me.
Who?
Uh, two men.
Brothers?
Well, how should I know?
-( door chimes )
-That could be them.
Don't answer it.
Believe me, I'm not planning to.
( lock beeping )
Sounds like they're trying
to bypass the lock.
Come on.
Computer, dim the lights.
( beeping )
Remind me to invest in a better lock.
( door opening )
QUARK: Gentlemen.
Quark, we've been looking
all over for you.
The latinum's on its way.
It'll be here tomorrow.
That's good news.
We were getting worried.
( door chimes )
Expecting anyone?
You never know who's going to drop by.
Don't answer it.
( lock beeping )
Sounds like they're coming in anyway.
You should invest in a better lock.
Whoever it is, get rid of them.
We'll be over there.
Um...
you'd be more comfortable in there.
We'll be back there.
Why didn't you answer the door?
Oh, I dozed off.
It's been one of those days.
We need to talk.
What would we need to talk about?
Are you all right?
What makes you ask that?
Well, you keep craning your neck.
Well, look what we have here.
I bet the Royal Family sleeps soundly
knowing you're on the job.
Royal Family?
What kind of lies
you been telling him, Hain?
The usual.
You know each other.
It's been a long time.
Nine years.
You know, it must be nine years.
I see you're still
a step behind everybody else.
Leave him alone, Hain.
Hey, it's Larell.
I can see that.
What's going on here?
We're, uh, having a little reunion.
We used to work together...
with Morn.
I guess that means
he wasn't a prince after all.
No.
And you're not a security agent.
And you're not really his ex-wife.
Please... please don't tell me
Morn didn't have any latinum.
Oh, he had latinum, all right.
At least that part is true.
Ever hear of the Lissepian
Mother's Day Heist?
Who hasn't?
While the entire world was celebrating,
someone broke into the Central Bank
and made off with...
One thousand bricks
of gold-pressed latinum.
Wait a minute.
You expect me to believe
that the four of you pulled that off?
There was five of us. Morn helped.
Yes, but then he ran off with the latinum.
Why did you take
so long to come after him?
Because we knew he'd stashed it
away somewhere
to wait for the statute
of limitations to expire.
And it did, two weeks ago.
You see, we can't be prosecuted anymore.
So here we are.
The latinum's en route.
Maybe we should just split it up
and go our separate ways.
The voice of reason.
Not you...
us.
Krit's right. We don't need him anymore.
So what do we do with him?
KRIT: It should look like an accident.
We don't want anyone asking questions.
Wait a minute. You can't kill me.
I'm the only one who can take
delivery of the latinum.
You need my thumb print.
If you stand still,
this won't hurt as much.
( screaming )
HAIN: Ah, ah, ah, wait a minute.
What do you propose, Nahsk?
That we walk into the Cargo Bay
with his bloody thumb,
and ask for the latinum?
We need him.
The only question is,
what happens after he takes delivery?
We could split the latinum... five ways.
That is what you would
have gotten if Morn was still alive.
That's true.
Think of me as Morn.
I can't believe I just said that.
This isn't fair. We stole it.
He had nothing to do with it.
Maybe not, but the bottom line
is you need me.
A thousand bricks of latinum
split five ways...
what do you think?
It's still a lot of latinum.
That's 250 bricks each.
So do we have a deal?
-All right.
-OK.
The Bolian transport
arrives tomorrow at 1600.
We'll meet at the cargo bay.
We're staying together until it gets here.
We are?
I don't trust you, and I certainly
don't trust them.
I see your point.
But I have a bar to run.
All right.
To your hospitality.
Don't mention it.
So this was Morn's favorite place?
He used to sit right there.
Well, that's not very smart
sitting with your back to the door.
He was the trusting type.
Which one of you killed him anyway?
It wasn't us.
Me neither.
Don't look at me.
Then it really was an accident.
Poor Morny. He always had such bad luck.
Get rid of him.
We're closed.
At this hour?
Friends of Morn.
We're... commiserating.
I see.
And how long are you going to be closed?
Oh, until about 1600 hours tomorrow.
We have a lot to commiserate about.
I see.
Where were we?
There it is.
Right on time.
Uh...
I believe that's for me.
Open it.
Oh...
I'll count it.
All right.
Somebody else count it.
Put it down, Hain. My brother may be slow,
but if you pull that trigger,
he'll kill you.
I'm not slow.
Nahsk...
what are you doing?
We're family.
Just put the gun down.
( weapons fire continues )
Go ahead.
Kill each other.
Oh...
( gasps )
ODO: Security. Drop your weapons.
-Huh?
-( weapons fire continues )
ODO: This is your last warning.
I said drop them.
( weapon clatters to ground )
LARELL: I surrender.
Take her to a holding cell.
Get the rest of them to the Infirmary.
Ah, there you are.
Are they gone?
From now on,
you'll be commiserating alone.
All your "friends" are going to prison.
For how long?
Assault with intent to kill?
Long enough.
Then it's mine.
All mine.
What you are about to hear
is the most beautiful sound in the galaxy.
Oh, that can't be.
There's no latinum in these bricks.
What?
Someone's extracted all the latinum!
There's nothing here but worthless gold.
And it's all yours.
( chuckling )
No.
No! No!
( grunting )
Quark? Quark?
What?
What do you want?
There's someone here to see you.
I thought you said
they were all going to prison.
You'd better sit down.
Morn?
Alive and well.
Apparently, he faked his own death,
but I'll let him tell you all about it.
Well?
No.
I don't want to hear it.
Not one word.
You set me up.
You left the latinum to me
because you knew I would do
whatever it would take
to get my hands on it.
You figured I could keep the four of them
off-balance long enough for them
to turn on themselves.
This whole thing was a scam
to get them off your back, wasn't it?
I could have been killed, you know.
And I thought we were friends.
I have to admit...
I didn't suspect for a minute.
Tell you the truth,
I didn't think you had it in you
to pull off something like this.
I just have one question for you.
What happened to the latinum?
( gurgling burp )
Of course. Your second stomach.
You've been keeping it
in your second stomach
all these years?
That's a lot of latinum.
No wonder your hair fell out.
For me?
That must be 100 bricks worth.
I don't know what to say.
Thanks.
Not that I didn't earn it
after all you put me through.
If you ever want to set
me up again, feel free.
You know...
you and I should consider
doing business together.
Two enterprising gentlemen like us
could do all right for ourselves.
Take that gold dust of yours...
it doesn't have to be a total loss.
I hear there's some primitive cultures
who consider it quite valuable.