The Defiant searched the
area for almost six hours.
We couldn't find
any sign of survivors.
The Cortéz was a good ship.
You knew Captain
Swofford a long time.
I introduced him to his wife.
Patrolling
the Cardassian borders
is getting
more and more dangerous.
You never know
when you're going to run
into a squadron
of Jem'Hadar fighters.
I guess we popped the
champagne cork too soon, huh?
Everyone thought
the war was over
when we retook the station
and pushed the Dominion
back into Cardassian space.
I never believed that,
and neither did you.
A lot of good that did
the 400 people on the Cortéz.
Ah. Mr. Sisko.
How do you like
our station so far?
Well, it certainly is...
big.
I heard about Quentin Swofford.
I'm sorry.
Look, Dad... I know I haven't
been very good company
in the last few days.
I didn't come here
to be entertained.
I came to see you and Jake.
Well...
you certainly picked
an interesting time
to take your first trip
away from Earth.
Well, I figured
it was now or never.
Besides, I've been
worried about you.
The last couple
of times we've talked
it seemed like you
were carrying the weight
of the entire Alpha Quadrant
on your shoulders.
Sometimes it certainly
feels that way.
Dad...
Just say it, Son.
I don't know
how much more I can take.
I don't know how many more
friends I can lose.
Every time I achieve
a real victory
something like this happens
and everything
seems to turn to ashes.
So what do you want to do?
Maybe it's time
for me to step down...
let someone else
make the tough calls.
I see.
No one is indispensable, Son.
Not even you.
Whatever decision you
make, I'll support.
Of course, if Quentin
Swofford was here
I bet he'd have a few things
to say to you.
But he's not here,
and that's the whole point.
I'd say you have
some thinking to do
and I've got a dinner
date with my grandson.
So you'd better get to it.
Who was that?
Where'd he go?
Who?
The man that just
walked by my door.
I didn't see anyone.
I could have sworn...
I don't know what you're
so worried about, Ben.
I'm not taking my ship
anywhere near
the Cardassian border.
I realize that, but the Dominion
is getting bolder and bolder
and your freighter is no match
for a Jem'Hadar attack ship.
Ah, they've got
to catch me first.
You're really not worried,
are you?
No. I'm fearless,
and you know that.
That's why you love me.
I think I follow that logic.
Hey, Benny!
Catch the game?
What?
Who was that?
Who was who?
Ben?
Where are you going?
Somebody needs to help him!
Call an ambulance! Oh!
He's awake now.
Ben, are you all right?
I think so.
Thank God.
Hey, Dad, you scared
us there for a minute.
What happened?
I don't know.
I'm reading some unusual
synaptic potentials.
Your neural patterns
are similar
to those you experienced
last year.
You mean... when I was having
those visions about Bajor?
Visions?
Does this have something
to do with those Prophets
you're always telling me about?
He's not going to need
surgery again, is he?
I'm not sure yet.
So I'd like you to remain
overnight for observation.
Is that absolutely necessary?
Take a look at these readings.
Hey, you going
to buy that or not?
...Shine little glow-worm,
glimmer, glimmer...
Now, personally, I don't
see the attraction.
Spaceships, flying
saucers, men from Mars.
What's wrong with men from Mars?
Nothing, except
it's all make-believe.
Me? I like war stories.
Did you see From
Here to Eternity?
Burt Lancaster standing there
in the middle of Pearl Harbor
machine gun blazing...
shooting down those Zeroes.
If it had been flying saucers...
forget about it.
So you going to buy that or not?
Benny!
Hello, Albert.
I, uh...
I thought you might be
going to the, uh...
the office.
We could walk there together.
Exactly. Uh, uh...
ah, there they are.
So, you're looking
at the Galaxy I see.
Paper here! Paper!
Voilà. A pitcher of plain water
instantly becomes
a pitcher of iced tea.
Incredible!
"White Rose Redi-Tea."
What an appalling concept.
Oh! H.G. Wells
would've liked it.
I doubt it.
No self-respecting
Englishman would.
Pabst!
Pabst, get out here.
What's wrong now, Herb?
I'll give you one guess.
Oh, the "Battle of the
Doughnuts," Round 28.
That's it?
That's what you
called me out here for...
to complain about the doughnuts?
They're stale again.
Delicious.
Delicious, my eye.
These are two days old,
and you know it.
I have been eating doughnuts
my whole life.
These weren't baked more than...
...six hours ago.
That's it.
I quit.
I'm going over to Galaxy.
Ha!
Galaxy? That rag?
- Who's winning?
- I bet that rag...
Draw, same as always.
You want to write
Galaxy? Go ahead.
But they're not going to pay you
four cents a word
for your stories.
You're paying him four cents
a word?
Stay out of this, Julius.
Did you see
where I put the uh?
The matches?
I gave them to you.
For that fantasy crap you write,
you're lucky to be getting two.
I beg your pardon?
- What's that?
- The latest Galaxy.
Benny has the new issue
of Galaxy.
Let me see that.
Heinlein, Bradbury, Sturgeon.
Quite a lineup.
Add Herbert Rossoff to them,
and it'd be complete.
What if I promise you
fresh doughnuts tomorrow?
Why should I believe you?
I'll even throw in
a couple of crullers.
Okay, I'll stay.
Don't do us any favors.
Good. Now that we've finished
with the old business,
on to the new.
Time to hand out next
month's story assignments.
Rittenhouse, we're waiting!
Okay, friends and neighbors.
Let's see what Uncle
Roy has for you today.
All right, I've titled this one
"Please Take Me With You."
Who wants it?
Hmm, what do you think, Jules?
I think we can do
something with that.
Oh, I'll bet you can.
I can see it now...
the lonely little girl
befriended by empathetic aliens
who teach her how to smile.
It's enough to make you go out
and buy a television set.
Next.
And this is
Mr. Pabst's favorite.
"Honeymoon on Andoras."
Oh, you've got to be kidding.
What? So I had
too much sauerkraut
on my franks that night.
What can I say?
Be that as it may, that is
the worst piece of garbage
- I have ever seen.
- Thank you.
I'll take it.
Of course, you will.
You have an affinity
for garbage, don't you?
The picture may be garbage
but the story...
the story will be art.
All right
I haven't got a title
for this one yet.
Anybody got any ideas?
I'll think of something.
All right,
next order of business.
Some of our readers
have been writing in
wanting to know
what you people look like.
Oh, write back and tell them
we look like writers...
poor, needy
and incredibly attractive.
Well, our publisher
has a better idea.
Mr. Stone has decided
to run a picture of you
in next month's issue.
Is that absolutely...
Necessary?
I'm afraid it is.
Kay, you can sleep
late that day.
Of course, I can.
God forbid
the public ever finds out
that K.C. Hunter is a woman.
I suppose I'm sleeping late
that day, too.
It's not personal, Benny,
but as far as our readers
are concerned
Benny Russell
is as white as they are.
Let's just keep it that way.
Oh, yes.
If the world's not ready
for a woman writer
imagine what would happen
if it learned
about a Negro with a typewriter.
Run for the hills.
It's the end of civilization.
What about W.E.B. Du Bois,
Zora Neale Hurston,
Langston Hughes, Ralph Ellison,
Richard Wright?
Did you ever hear of Native Son?
That's literature
for liberals and intellectuals.
The average reader's not going
to spend his hard-earned cash
on stories written by Negroes.
Would someone please shoot me
and put me out of my misery?
Oh, how I long for a gun.
I'm sorry, Benny.
I wish things were different,
but they're not.
Wishing never changed
a damn thing.
Come on, Benny,
it's just a photo.
I'll try to remember that.
You're a dog.
All right,
enough standing around.
Get back to work.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What's the hurry?
That's my drawing.
Is that so?
Nice suit.
Where'd you get it?
I bought it.
Can I have my drawing back?
Hey, boy, I'd watch that tone
of voice if I were you.
What are you doing around here?
I work here.
Yeah? Where?
In there.
What are you, the janitor?
Awfully well-dressed
for a janitor.
How do we know
that picture's yours?
It's the drawing
of a space station.
Space station?
Hey, hey...
hey, hey.
Well, get off it already.
Okay, okay.
See?
It's not worth anything
except to me.
I say we run him in,
check him for priors.
Nah... we got to be uptown
in 15 minutes.
Take your drawing...
and get out of here.
Hey, hey. You're getting off
with a warning this time.
Next time, not so lucky.
Now, get out of here.
You heard him... move on.
I don't know, Kevin.
This whole city's going
to hell in a handbasket, huh?
Damn shame.
Come on.
And he said to me...
"these words are
trustworthy and true.
"And the Lord, God of the
spirits of the Prophets,
"has sent an angel
to show his servants
what must soon take place."
Praise the Lord.
Open their eyes.
Help them to see.
Are you talking to me?
"Oh, that my words
were now written.
Oh, that they were printed
in a book."
Write those words,
Brother Benny.
Let them see the glory
of what lies ahead.
"B-Benny"?
How do you know my name?
Go now and write the truth
that's in your heart...
the truth
"that shall set them free."
Praise be the word
of the Lord.
Praise to the word
of the Prophets!
Doo-wa, doo-wa,
doo-wa, doo-wa
Hey, doo-wa, doo-wa
Doo-wa, doo-wa
Hey, bop
Bop, bop, bop, ba.
Hey, baby.
Have a seat.
The usual?
How about scrambling
those eggs today?
Oh, my.
Aren't we feeling adventurous.
I have just written
the best story of my life.
Well, that's great, baby.
Um... I've got
some good news, too.
I talked
to Mrs. Jackson last night
and she's serious
about retiring
in the next couple of years.
I asked her about selling
this place to us
and she said
that she would be willing.
Cassie, we have been over this.
I have a job; I am a writer.
And how much money have
you earned doing that?
I've only been working
at it for a few years.
A few years?
More like 15,
if you count all those stories
you wrote in the Navy.
That was amateur stuff.
Oh, baby.
Neither one of us is
getting any younger.
Can't you see?
This is our chance.
We can make some money.
We can get married.
You're always talking about
writing for the future.
Well, look around you.
This is our future.
Cassie, hear the game
last night?
Went two for four,
robbed Snider of a tater.
Should've heard the crowd...
yelling and carrying on.
Sure, they were yelling.
They want to know why the Giants
are in fifth place.
Would you please tell this fool
to take his business
someplace else?
Well, I thought about it.
Trouble is, if he did leave,
he'd take my heart with him.
Well, suit yourself.
But if you ask me
it's a waste
of a very pretty heart.
I don't think so.
Strike three.
You're out.
Oh, that's all right.
I'll get another turn at bat.
How about some steak and eggs?
Ah, coming right up.
Uh, but tell me something.
How come you
still living uptown?
I mean, a famous
ballplayer like you
you can live anywhere you want.
The hell I can.
They can hardly
get used to the idea
of me playing alongside them.
Living next door to them?
That's a whole other story.
Besides, around here,
when people look at me
it's 'cause they admire me.
There, I'm just
another colored boy
that can hit a curveball.
Now, if you will excuse me,
my public awaits.
Ladies?
Oh, hi, guys. Yeah.
I'll see about those eggs.
Hey, hey, Benny.
You want to buy a watch?
How did you get that?
I found it.
Nice, huh?
Jimmy, you got
to turn this around
or one day you're going
to find yourself
in some serious trouble.
Anything I can get into,
I can get out.
You keep thinking that way
and watch what happens.
Man, why you always
trying to lecture me?
I'm not trying
to lecture you, Jimmy.
I'm just trying to help.
You want to help me?
You can buy this watch.
I can use the cash.
Why don't you get a job?
As what? A delivery boy
or a dishwasher?
No, thanks.
I like being my own boss,
setting my own hours.
Sounds like a great life.
Yours ain't no better...
writing stories about
a bunch of white people
living on the moon.
Man, who cares about that?
Hey, I'm not doing that anymore.
I'm writing about us.
What, colored people
on the moon?
Check out next month's issue.
Colored people on the moon.
I just might do that.
But first, I'm going to need
to raise me some cash.
Oh!
She's got a worm in her belly.
Oh, that's disgusting.
That's interesting,
but that's disgusting.
And you
uh, um...
if you don't mind my asking,
that is
you... you are?
I'm Mr. Pabst's new secretary,
Darlene Kursky.
Which one of yous wrote this?
I did.
You?
Surprised?
Well... it's just, it's
the best thing I've read
since The Puppet Masters.
I read a lot of science fiction.
Bless you, my child.
The world needs
more people like you.
This story is really...
It's... um... uh...
How should I put it?
It's... it's very...
Impressive?
Yes.
It's a damn fine piece
of writing is what it is.
And "Deep Space Nine"
is a very intriguing title.
Very admirable.
The master of understatement.
What he really means is
he wishes he had
half your talent.
You know what, Benny?
I like this Major of yours.
She's a tough cookie.
Science fiction needs
more strong women characters.
I'm always saying that,
aren't I, Jules?
Ad nauseam, dear.
These Cardassians...
I like the way
you described them
especially the neck ridges.
I'm going to do some sketches
for you to take a look at.
Make a nice cover.
Don't waste your time.
You, get back to work.
Right away, Mr. Pabst.
You, too, Roy.
Douglas, you're not
going to stand there
and tell us you
don't like this story.
Oh, I like it, all right.
It's good.
It's very good.
But you know I can't print it.
Why not?
Oh, come on, Benny.
Your hero's a Negro captain
the head of a space station,
for Christ's sake.
What's wrong with that?
People won't accept it.
It's not believable.
And men from Mars are?
Stay out of this, Herb.
Look, Benny
I am a magazine editor.
I am not a crusader.
I'm not here
to change the world.
I'm here to put out
a magazine, that's my job.
That means I have to answer
to the publisher
the national distributors,
the wholesalers
and none of them
are going to want
to put this story
on the newsstand.
For all we know, it could
cause a race riot.
Congratulations, Douglas.
That's
the most imbecilic attempt
to rationalize personal
cowardice that I've ever heard.
Oh. He's angry now.
Huh! Herb's been angry
ever since Josef Stalin died.
What's that supposed to mean?
You know exactly
what it means.
- You calling me a Red?!
- Easy, easy!
Calm down, dear boy.
We're writers, not Vikings.
I'm not going to stand here
and let some craven fascist
call me a pinko
and get away with it.
Douglas, um...
what did you think
of, uh... of my story?
I loved it.
You see, Albert's
got the right idea.
He's not interested
in Negroes or whites.
He writes about robots.
That's because he is a robot.
No offense, Albert.
Well, I...
like robots.
They're very...
uh-uh, efficient.
Here. Write me a novella
based on this picture.
I'll print it
in next month's issue.
You do a good job,
you might even get the cover.
What about my story?
Look, the way I see it
you can either burn it
or stick it
in a drawer
for the next 50 years
or however long
it takes the human race
to become color-blind.
I want people to read it now.
Fine.
You want me to print it?
Make the captain white.
That's not what I wrote!
It's your call.
I'm sorry they didn't
buy your story, baby.
Really, I am.
I told you
you were wasting your time.
A colored captain.
The only reason
they'll ever let us in space
is if they need someone
to shine they shoes.
Ain't that right, Cassie?
I don't know, and to be honest
I don't much care what happens
a hundred years from now.
It's today that matters.
Well, I've got news for you.
Today or 100 years from now...
it don't make
a bit of difference.
As far as they're concerned,
we'll always be niggers.
Things are going to change.
They have to.
Oh, you keep
telling yourself that.
Maybe this is all happening
for a reason.
You mean, maybe it's God's way
of telling me
that I should quit writing
and go
into the restaurant business?
Hey, it's possible.
Baby, I know
we can make this work for us.
We could be happy.
Besides, you don't
have to give up
writing altogether.
Maybe you could write something
for the Amsterdam News
or... some other
Negro newspaper.
I'm not a reporter.
I'm a writer.
I write fiction
and the Amsterdam News
is not going to publish stories
about a space station
400 years into the future.
Hear the game last night?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
You don't look so good.
You sick or something?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
You want to lie
down in the back?
No, no, no, I...
I just need some air.
Are, are we still
on for tonight?
I'll pick you up about 10:00.
Well, what are you doing
till 10:00?
Whatever it is,
I won't be doing it with you.
Hello, Brother Benny.
You again.
I don't understand
what you want from me.
To follow the path
of the Prophets.
Walk with the Prophets,
Brother Benny.
Show us the way.
What way?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Write the words,
Brother Benny...
the words that will lead
us out of the darkness
onto the path
of righteousness!
Write the words, Brother Benny!
Write the words!
Hey, baby.
Hey, hey, hey.
You forgot all about our date.
Oh... our date.
I'm sorry.
I was working.
Ben Sisko?
Isn't that your colored captain?
Mm-hmm.
Why are you writing
another one of those stories?
You couldn't sell the last one.
What makes you think this one
will be any different?
It probably won't be,
but it doesn't matter.
It's what I've got to do.
Right now, what you've
got to do is eat.
I'm not hungry.
What time is it anyway?
It's after midnight.
I should be getting
home to bed.
But before I go, what do you say
we take a spin
on the dance floor?
Okay.
Mmm. Feels good, doesn't it?
I could stay like this forever.
Mmm, me, too.
It's times like these
that I wish we'd never heard
of the Dominion.
The Dominion?!
What do you mean?
You said something
about the Dominion.
What is it, Ben?
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I think I'm losing my mind.
What? Tell me,
tell me what's wrong.
I'm starting to see
things from my story.
It's as if I'm becoming
this Captain Sisko.
Okay, baby, you just need
to get some rest.
It's all right.
I'm with you.
I'm with you, baby.
Just take it easy.
Shh.
Have you lost your mind?!
Lately, I've been asking myself
the same question.
I give you a novella to write.
I even offer you
a shot at the cover.
Three weeks later,
instead of a novella
you come back
with six stories...
six sequels to a story
I refused to publish
in the first place.
So I guess the answer
to the question
we've both been asking
is, yeah, you are certifiable.
I think you should print
your own stories, you know.
Through a private
publishing house.
A nice, elegant volume...
50 to 100 copies.
That's a great idea.
Yeah, might as well write it
in chalk on the sidewalk.
More people
would read it that way.
I've got an idea.
Why not make them,
you know, a, uh...
a d-dream?
What's that?
Just make the ending
of your first story
of "Deep Space Nine" a...
dream.
Would that make a difference?
That depends.
On what?
On who's doing the dreaming.
Well, obviously someone, uh...
someone without a lot of hope.
A-a shoeshine boy, a convict...
someone dreaming
of a better future.
A Negro.
Yeah.
Well, I suppose it'd have to be
if he was dreaming
about a Negro captain.
Hold on.
Making it a dream
guts the story.
Shut up, Herb!
I think
it makes it more poignant.
What about
the other Sisko stories?
He can't make them all dreams.
Let him get
this one published first
then he can worry
about the others.
What do you think, Benny?
I think...
it's better than chalk
on the sidewalk.
Six, seven...
Can I play?
Hey, Jimmy, I got great news.
We're headed for the stars.
Yeah, sure, whatever.
Oh, come on.
I'll buy you lunch.
I'll tell you all about it.
Later. I got some business
to take care of.
Oh? What kind of business?
Big time.
That's all I got to say.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hold it, hold it.
What are you talking about?
Don't worry about it.
It's cool, man, I got
it under control.
Huh?
I'll see you around.
Bottom of the seventh,
I'm up again.
0-2 fastball... bam!...
into the left field bleachers.
Had to be 400 feet.
I know all about it, Willie.
I read the newspaper.
Oh, but you got to admit...
they don't tell it
like I tell it.
Hey, Cassie!
Hey, man, did you hear
the game last night?
I went two for four.
Yeah, Willie, that's great.
But I just hit a grand slam.
They are publishing one
of my Sisko stories, sugar,
at three cents a word...
three cents a word!
Oh, good for you, baby!
That means tonight
we are celebrating.
Dancing, the works.
I'll wear my red dress.
You're damn...
right you will.
Three cents a word.
Whoo!
Hey! There you are.
Oh! Oh, my poor feet.
Baby, you better marry me soon.
I'm not getting any younger.
Yes, but you are
getting more beautiful
day by day.
I'd be happy
just to spend my life
Waiting on your beck and call...
Brother Benny.
I was hoping I'd see you again.
I did it.
My story's getting published.
"And the light of the Lord
is in his path."
But, Brother Benny
this is only the beginning
of your journey
not the ending.
And the path of the Prophets
sometimes leads
into darkness and pain.
Benny, what is he talking about?
Who are you?
I speak with the voice
of the Prophets.
And in their words,
hope and despair
walk arm in arm.
Did you understand
any of that?
Is that gunfire?
Hey! Hey! Whoa, whoa!
What happened?
What's it to you?
I know him.
Oh, yeah? Well, then
maybe you can explain
what he was doing trying to
break into this car here.
Is that why you shot him,
because he was breaking
into a car?!
He had a weapon.
A crowbar!
Yeah, now, step back.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
Hey!
Stop it! Stop it!
Let him go!
Stop it, please!
Get off of me!
Stop it!
You're going to kill him!
Stop!
I'm telling you, baby.
You've been cooped up in
this apartment for weeks.
Going down to the office
will do you good.
I suppose you're right.
I should be there
when the first copies
of this month's issue
are delivered.
Absolutely.
After all that work you did
you deserve to see
your story in print.
Just no jumping up and
down with excitement.
Wouldn't want you
to hurt yourself.
I will restrict myself
to a proud grin.
You're not having any more of
those hallucinations, are you?
I'm fine.
What about
"It came from Outer Space?"
I think it's a smashing title.
I wish I'd thought of it.
Hey, Benny.
Long time no see.
Is it here?
Not yet.
Pabst is still at the printer.
We're waiting
for his return
with bated breath.
We, uh, heard that...
that you were...
Heard they beat the hell
out of you.
I'm okay.
Glad to see that you're...
you know, up... and about.
Tell him the good news, Albert.
Yeah.
Oh, it's-it's nothing.
Nothing?
He sells a novel to Gnome Press
and he says it's nothing?
Novel, Albert.
Congratulations.
Oh, thank you.
Robots, huh?
What else?
It's about time.
Douglas... magazine?
There isn't any magazine...
not this month anyway.
Mr. Stone had the entire run
pulped.
He can't do that.
Oh, he can... and he did.
He believes, quote,
"This issue did not
live up to our usual
high standards," unquote.
Well... what, what's that
supposed to mean?
It means he didn't like it.
Which means the public
will simply have to get along
without any "Incredible Tales"
this month.
What exactly is it
that he did not like?
The-the-the artwork,
the... the layout?
Uh, what "high standards"
is he talking about?
Take it easy, Benny.
No, I...
It's about my story, isn't it?
That's what this is all about.
He didn't want
to publish my story
and we all know why.
Because my hero
is a colored man.
Hey! This magazine
belongs to Mr. Stone.
If he doesn't want
to publish this month
we don't publish this month...
end of story.
That doesn't make it right
and you know it.
Don't tell me what I know.
Besides, it's not
about what's right.
It's about what is.
And I'm afraid I've got some
more bad news for you, Benny.
Mr. Stone has decided
that your services
are no longer required here.
What?!
You're firing me?
I have no choice, Benny.
It's his decision.
Well, you can't fire me.
I quit.
To hell with you...
and to hell with Stone!
Try to stay calm, Benny.
No! I'm tired of being calm.
Calm never got me a damn thing.
I'm warning you, Benny.
If you don't stop this
I'm going to call the police.
You go ahead!
Call them!
Call anybody you want.
They can't do anything to me.
Not anymore...
and nor can any of you!
I... am a human being, damn it.
You can deny me all you want...
but you cannot deny Ben Sisko.
He exists.
That future, that space station,
all those people...
they exist in here.
In my mind, I created it.
And every one of you know it.
You read it.
It's here!
You, you, you hear
what I'm telling you?!
You can pulp a story,
but you cannot destroy an idea.
Don't you understand?
That's ancient knowledge.
You cannot destroy an idea.
That future...
I created it, and it's real!
Don't you understand?
It is real!
I created it, and it's real!
It's real.
Oh, God!
Easy.
Two, three...
Rest easy, Brother Benny.
You have walked in the
path of the Prophets.
There is no greater glory.
Tell me, please.
Who am I?
Don't you know?
Tell me.
You are the dreamer...
and the dream.
Ben?
How long was I out?
Only for a few minutes.
Seemed like forever to me.
That's odd.
Somehow your neural patterns
have returned to normal.
That's good, isn't it?
Oh, it's very good.
I just don't understand
how it happened.
How are you feeling, Son?
I'm okay.
I'm done packing.
Transport leaves
at 8:00 in the morning.
I wish you could stay longer.
I've got to get back
to the restaurant.
Ah, my customers have never
gone this long without me.
The question is:
What are you going to do?
The only thing I can do.
Stay here
and finish the job I started
and if I fail...
"I have fought the good fight.
"I have finished the course.
I have kept the faith."
I've never known you
to quote from the Bible.
I'm full of surprises,
aren't I?
And so are you.
Sounds like that dream
you had... helped you
sort things out.
I suppose it did.
But I have begun to wonder.
What if it wasn't a dream?
What if this life we're leading,
all of this...
you and me, everything...
what if all of this
is the illusion?
That's a scary thought.
I know. I know.
But maybe, just maybe...
Benny isn't the dream.
We are.
Maybe we're nothing more
than figments
of his imagination.
For all we know...
at this very moment
somewhere far beyond
all those distant stars...
Benny Russell...
is dreaming of us.