Captain's Log, Stardate 51474.2.
The Defiant has been ordered
to investigate a rare subspace
compression phenomenon
recently discovered
in Federation space.
This scientific assignment
is a welcome change
from months of combat duty
against the Dominion.
Three of my officers
are taking a runabout
into the anomaly's vortex.
The runabout and its crew
will be subjected
to sever spatial distortion,
so we have activated a tractor
beam to minimize the effect.
So, uh... how small are they?
The miniaturization
process won't begin
until the runabout reaches the
edge of the accretion disk.
I see. And, uh...
then they'll begin to shrink?
Yes, sir.
Major, are you laughing
at our investigation
of this subspace anomaly?
No, sir.
The data collected here could
provide Starfleet with the key
to creating transwarp corridors
through space.
It could give us
a substantial tactical advantage
over the Dominion.
Oh, it's very
important research.
What?!
I'm not laughing.
I... just because
we are shrinking three people
to the size of coffee cups...
Smaller, actually.
I do not see what is so humorous
about being small.
Neither do I.
On screen.
Their visual signal's
degrading, Captain.
We have audio only.
Go ahead, Rubicon.
We're about to enter
the accretion disk.
I wish I were with you, old man.
I'll send you a postcard.
Tell Worf I look forward
to hearing his poem.
I bet it'll be inspiring...
We'll talk again once we've left
the accretion disk and reversed
the effects of the compression.
Rubicon out.
Good luck, Rubicon.
We've lost their signal,
Captain.
Thank you, Ensign.
Mr. Worf.
Poem?
It is an ancient
Klingon tradition
to commemorate
an important event
with a poem.
Jadzia asked me to compose one
for this occasion.
Well, what have you got so far?
They've penetrated
the accretion disk.
Now, is it my imagination
or did the kid
just cover for him?
This could be the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
They are getting smaller.
Even the space
within their subatomic structure
is shrinking.
I wonder what it feels like.
I don't feel any smaller.
Well, believe it or not
you're about a meter tall
and shrinking fast.
In a few minutes
you're going to be half the size
of a combadge.
There's a comforting thought.
The gamma ray flux
is increasing.
We should close
the blast shutters.
Take a last look.
We're on sensors from here on.
You're sure we'll return
to our normal size
once we clear the anomaly?
The probes did.
You saw the data.
Something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
I'm... just not in love
with the idea of being small.
What are you smirking at?
You're as small as I am.
Actually, you're sitting
1.14 meters closer
to the focal point
of the anomaly,
which means you've shrunk
.04 percent more than I have.
What was that?
The tractor beam is fluctuating.
Something's wrong.
The Jem'Hadar are coming around
for another pass!
Radiation from the vortex
must have masked
their warp signature.
Return fire, Mr. Worf.
Ensign,
pull the Rubicon out of there.
Phasers are off-line.
We're a sitting duck
as long as we're tethered
to the runabout.
I'm not going to leave them
in there if I can help it.
Mr. Worf, go down
to Auxiliary Control
and target the phasers manually.
Aye, sir.
I'm losing the Rubicon, sir.
If we're going
to get out of here
I need warp power now!
I'm on it.
Report.
Shield generators and impulse
engines are off-line, sir.
Warp engines, too.
Surrender
or you will all be killed.
Chief, you okay?
I think so.
Julian?
I'm fine, but you're not.
Oh, that's better.
That was the easy part.
Well, the good news
is we're alive, so we
must have escaped the anomaly.
The bad news
is the external sensors
and the com system are down.
I can patch around most of
the damage, but it'll take time.
Better add the blast
shutters to your list.
I can't get them open.
There you go.
Good as new.
Oh, you don't suppose
that thing'll work
on our
communications system?
I'm picking up the Defiant's
transponder signal.
We can home in on that.
Going to one-quarter impulse.
Chief, either
open these shutters
or give me external sensors...
whichever's quicker.
I need to see
where we're going.
The Bridge is secure.
Tactical report.
The Bridge officers
are confined in the mess hall...
other survivors
in the cargo bay.
We will have impulse power
back on line in 30 minutes
but it will take several hours
to restore warp capability.
It must be gratifying
for an Elder
to end his career
with a victory.
I feel privileged
to be here with you
at such a moment.
There is still much to do
before we declare victory.
Until we leave
Federation space
we are vulnerable to...
I am First
and I have declared victory.
That is, of course,
your prerogative.
Open a channel to the Vorta.
Yes, First.
We have the boarding party.
Ah, First. Your report?
The Defiant is ours.
Good. Very, very good.
I must admit, I was
initially quite skeptical
about you
and the other new Jem'Hadar
bred in this Quadrant, but this
is a most impressive debut.
Wouldn't you agree, Elder?
The takeover of the ship
was competently executed.
Do I detect a note of jealousy
in your voice?
I'm sure it must be difficult
for you to watch
a new race of Jem'Hadar
beginning to supplant you
and the other members
of the old guard.
I serve the Founders.
If it is their will
to create a new race
then that is
the order of things.
But?
But the Jem'Hadar bred
here in the Alpha Quadrant
have not proven
themselves superior
to those in the Gamma Quadrant...
at least not yet.
Not yet?
It is the Alphas
who made this victory possible.
If it were not for us,
you would never...
You two can argue about this
on your own time.
First, how long
until you restore warp power?
I will make a complete
survey of the ship
and give you a report
in one hour.
Very well.
I await your report.
Bring me Captain Sisko.
I would suggest
that his execution can wait
until we have completed repairs
to the ship.
I'm not going to execute him.
Are you about to question
my order, Second?
No.
Obedience brings victory.
And victory is life.
Find the ship's transponder
and shut it down.
I don't want anyone tracking us.
Yes, First.
And get these chairs
off the Bridge.
Thanks.
That's enough.
I should have foreseen this.
I should have sent out
reconnaissance probes
to scan for enemy ships
or a shuttle
or recalibrated the sensors.
If I had, Jadzia...
None of that would
have done any good.
The Jem'Hadar approached us
from the anterior angle
of the anomaly.
Their warp...
signature...
He's just trying
to tell you that...
I do not need him
to tell me anything.
Everybody settle.
First of all, we don't know
what happened to the Rubicon.
For all we know, they got
out of the anomaly on their own.
If they did, they're headed home
and in much better
shape than we are.
So let's hold off on analyzing
our mistakes for now.
If they restore warp power,
we'll be analyzing them
from inside
a Dominion prison camp.
Restoring warp power...
might not be so simple for them.
It took us a week
just to learn how to pilot
one of their ships.
We might have a chance
to retake the Defiant
but we can't do anything
unless we can get
out of this room.
Suggestions?
Captain Sisko...
come with me.
Everybody sit tight.
I'll be back.
We've lost the Defiant's
transponder signal.
Coming to a full stop.
The problem isn't at this end.
They must have
stopped transmitting.
I can't keep
flying blind, Chief.
Try the shutters.
Nice work.
Ask and ye shall receive.
What the hell is that?
Some kind of wall?
In the middle of nowhere?
Wait a minute.
There's a symbol up there.
It looks like
a large black circle.
Anything else?
Hold on.
Chief...
you're not going to like this.
I thought you said we'd return
to our normal size
once we left the anomaly.
We should have.
We didn't leave the anomaly
by the same path by
which we entered it.
So the process failed
to reverse itself.
Are you telling me
I'm going to be
this bloody tall
for the rest of my life?
This bloody tall, actually.
But don't worry...
all we have to do
to regain our original size
is reenter the anomaly
and follow our original
trajectory back out.
In theory.
Well, I'll tell you
what isn't a theory.
We're going to need
the Defiant's help
to reenter the anomaly.
With communications out,
how do we get their attention?
Fly up to a window and knock?
Wait.
If we're... this big?
That means the Rubicon
is what, this big?
More or less.
And the Defiant's aft
plasma vent is...
this big?
Are you suggesting
that we take the Rubicon
inside the Defiant?
Well, why not?
Getting past the anti-back flow
valve might be tricky
but once we're inside
we've a better chance
of attracting
someone's attention than
we do sitting out here.
I love it. Let's go.
The engineering team reports
that we can start
the impulse engines
in 12 minutes.
Good.
Captain Benjamin Sisko...
the one the Bajorans
call "the Emissary."
I am First Kudak'Etan.
In a strange way,
you are the reason I exist.
If you had not
eliminated our fleet
in the wormhole,
there would have been no need
to breed Alpha Quadrant
Jem'Hadar.
You didn't bring me
here to say "thank you."
No. The impulse
engine sustained
only minor damage
in our attack
but the warp drive
was severely damaged.
I will need
your technical expertise
in order to repair it.
Bring Captain Sisko
to the Engine Room
so he may begin
necessary repairs.
It's a mistake.
Giving him access
to the Engine Room
will only give him
an opportunity
to retake the ship.
In fact, he's working on a plan
at this very moment.
I was not aware
that telepathy was
a Gamma characteristic.
I know what he's thinking
because it's exactly
what I would be doing
in his position.
You should kill him now
before he has a chance
to put his plan into motion.
You are the Second.
I am the First.
Do not presume to tell me
what to do.
I'm glad the two of you
worked that out.
Now, what makes you think
I'm going to help you?
Your choice is to repair
the warp drive
or watch me execute
your crew one at a time.
Have Sixth Duran'Adar
select one of the prisoners
for execution
and bring him to the Bridge.
I can't do this job alone.
I'm going to need
some of my crew.
How many?
I strongly suggest
you refuse this request.
You have the weapons.
Are you afraid you can't handle
a few unarmed prisoners?
I won't be baited
by a prisoner...
and neither should you.
Okay, I'm in no hurry
to reach a Dominion
prison camp.
If you want me to teach your men
how to repair a warp drive,
that's fine with me.
We'll begin with primary command
and control systems.
That should take
about six hours...
then we will move up
to basic engineering theory
for a class-7 warp drive.
Then...
Enough!
You may have the other three
Bridge officers
but that is all.
And I'm not interested in any
more of your "suggestions."
Now take him to the Engine Room.
Where are we, Chief?
We've just about reached
the bipolar flow junction,
I think.
You think?
Well, I'm not used to seeing
things from this perspective.
Once we reach the flow junction,
we should be able to go up
into the secondary warp
plasma feed
and then exit
by the diagnostic panel.
This conduit's filthy, Chief.
Don't you ever clean up
in here?
All right, all right.
Let's not badger the Chief.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
It was very small of me.
Whatever it is you're planning
don't.
I'll be watching you
and at the first sign
of treachery
I will kill
all your Bridge officers.
I'm a prisoner.
I have no intention...
The First may be a fool,
but I am not.
Then it is a pity for you
that you are not the First.
I was...
until two days ago.
If we had captured you
while I was in command
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
Deck Two, Section Five.
What happened?
He is an Alpha.
I am a Gamma.
His DNA
and psychological profile
are specifically designed
for combat in this Quadrant.
The Founders believe
that makes him a better leader.
What do you believe?
I believe I've given you
enough information already.
We have restored impulse power
and the warp drive
will be operational
in five hours.
Excellent. It's good to see
my faith in you
has not been misplaced.
The Founders will be pleased.
If you require
no more assistance
I will resume
our mission to Coridan.
Let's hope the Federation's
dilithium miners
will be as surprised to see us
as the Defiant's crew was.
Victory is life.
Indeed.
Set course for the nearest
Dominion outpost.
Engage impulse engines.
Uh-oh.
What is it?
The magnetic plasma
guides are heating up.
They must have initiated
the impulse prestart sequence.
What does that mean then?
It means this entire conduit
is about to be filled
with superheated plasma.
When you say "superheated"...
If I can't find
another way out of here
we'll be vaporized.
Is that clear?
Crystal.
There's a distribution
manifold coming up.
Take the left conduit.
Then make a quick right
into the relays.
Left... then right.
I hope you know
where you're going, Chief.
So do I.
Through the relays.
There's an inspection
hatch coming up
on the right.
If we can figure out a way
to open the ha...
We're out of time.
What about the hatch?
We'll have to open it
the old-fashioned way.
Let's not do that again.
No promises.
So where are we, Chief?
We should be
in the Engine Room
near the warp core.
Right.
There's the core.
Looks like the warp
drive is off-line.
Quite a mess.
I wonder what happened.
I will verify
the settings myself.
What are you doing?
Realigning the dilithium
articulation frame.
Instruct him on how to
complete the realignment.
It'll take longer
to explain than just to...
Then explain it quickly.
Give him the tool.
All right.
Start by decoupling
the lateral microbrace.
That's not good.
Chief, I need visual sensors
as fast as you can
get them to me.
Right.
Julian, give me a hand
down here.
Okay, you should have
visual sensors now.
The com system's
back on line.
They're forcing our crew
to repair the warp drive.
Why's the Captain
going along with this?
Good question.
But if I know Benjamin,
he's up to something.
Can you give me a tight shot
on the operations display?
I think so.
Do you see what I see?
Hmm. Very clever.
Oh, the problem is
it's never going to work.
The Bridge control lockouts.
The security codes are hardwired
through
the encryption circuitry.
Will someone please let me
in on this conversation?
The Captain's trying
to take control
of the ship from Engineering.
Kira is
the only one actually
working on the warp drive
but it doesn't look
like she's in any hurry
to get it done.
I think Worf's trying
to cover their tracks.
It looks like he's sending
false signals
to the computer system.
Nog is the key.
He's trying to override
the Bridge control lockout
so he can release
the command codes.
If he can do that
the Captain can control
the entire ship
from the operations console.
Nog's a smart kid,
but it's going to take him weeks
to release the codes from here.
Can we do anything to help him?
Not from Engineering.
If we could get to the Bridge
we could release the codes
from there.
How?
Wait a minute.
One thing at a time.
First, we need to get
out of the Engine Room
without getting caught.
Why is the Klingon working
on the plasma
displace subsystem?
Because I told him to.
That system has nothing to do
with warp drive operation.
Maybe not on Dominion ships,
but I'll need to use the display
to monitor
warp plasma stability.
Pardon me.
Seventh, power up
the magneto-impellers
and advance the field coils.
Call out every five teslas
until I tell you to stop.
Yes, Major.
Easy does it.
We don't want
to burn out the inducers.
Now what?
Now we wait until someone
walks out that door.
Sixth!
Yes, Second.
Relieve the Klingon.
Take over the repair
of the display subsystem.
Immediately, Second!
Give the Klingon another task.
Why?
Because I said so.
Why is the warp drive
not on line yet?
He's stalling.
"Stalling"?
Your Second is the one
who's slowing down the work.
He countermands my orders
arbitrarily reassigns my crew.
I can't get any work
done in here!
You were told to watch them,
not to interfere with them.
You're playing
right into his hands.
Don't you see that?
Captain Sisko...
you have 30 minutes
to restore warp power
or I will kill... her
and another of your crew
every 15 minutes
until you do.
And you, Second, will no longer
interfere with their work.
Get ready.
When he activates
the door sensor, we'll...
Nice bit of piloting.
If you liked that
you're going to love
what's coming up next.
Any luck, Ensign?
Not yet, sir.
The system is always
three steps ahead of me.
Every time I get past
the primary security net
the secondary
always kicks me back out
and the codes are all reset
and I have to start
all over again.
Ah... Like that.
Do you have a backup plan
in case this doesn't work?
Yes.
I'll destroy the ship.
There are still a few algorithms
I haven't tried yet.
Thanks.
All right, I'm ready to connect
the deuterium injector.
Go to the plasma relay
and power it up...
but slowly,
just like I showed you.
I'm about ten minutes away
from initiating
the prestart sequence
in the warp drive.
How's Nog doing?
Not good. You'll have
to find another problem.
Too fast!
Reinitialize the system
and start again
but do it at about half
the speed this time.
Well, he's not stupid.
He's already got the entire
command and control system
committed to memory.
I can't keep him fooled forever.
In a battle of wits
between you and him
I'll bet on you every time.
Hmm. What kind of odds
are you giving?
First?
I've realigned
the targeting sensors.
There were errors
in the tracking subroutines.
You were not ordered
to check the targeting sensors.
Well, I thought it
a wise precaution
in case we encountered
an enemy ship on our way home.
Your initiative pleases me.
It's a trait
that the Gammas lack.
Well, the Gammas
have many flaws.
When we return from this mission
there will be need
for a new Second.
I will recommend you
to the Vorta.
You will not be disappointed.
I'm sure that I won't.
It'll be Alphas like us
that determine the
future of this Quadrant.
That will be the
new order of things.
Looks like we need another
ticket into the Bridge.
So how long do we wait
for someone to open the door?
We don't.
I cannot access
the auto-destruct system
without drawing attention.
Plant a computer virus
in the warp plasma
subprocessor.
Set it to cause a core breach
once the ship reaches warp 1.
Understood.
Don't hit it too hard.
It could shatter
the control panel.
Don't worry.
I have a light touch.
Not according to Worf.
What?
Well, we certainly can't release
the control lock
while the First
has his hand on it.
Can we bypass it?
Well, I suppose I could reroute
the encryption
subprocessors manually.
But?
But I'd have to leave
the ship to do it.
And I have to say, I'm
not fond of the idea.
I can think of a thousand ways
a one-centimeter man
could get fried
walking around
inside a circuit housing.
Relax, Miles.
You wouldn't be able
to go out there
even if you wanted to.
You wouldn't be able to breathe.
The oxygen molecules outside
are almost 2,000 times
larger than anything
your hemoglobin
could assimilate.
You'd suffocate.
Well.
That takes care of that idea.
Unless...
Circuit housings are airtight.
I could beam a bubble
of compressed air
ahead of you, and it would
expand to fill the housing.
Well, it should work.
I mean, the air
would be thin, but, uh...
you'd be able to breathe
for about 20 minutes.
And then?
You'd pass out.
We'd pass out.
You're coming with me.
This might take longer
than I thought.
All right.
If we beamed in
to the primary safeties junction
we should see a cluster
of heuristic subprocessors...
next to a rectilinear
expansion module.
The question is:
What does a rectilinear
expansion module look like
when you're one centimeter tall?
What?
I haven't the faintest idea...
but it's amazing.
It's like we're in the middle
of an optronic forest.
Looks like we need to go...
Julian, stop!
That chip behind you
is carrying 20 microamps
of electric current.
Now that's not very much...
But it's enough to fry
every synapse in my tiny body.
Thanks for the tip.
All right, stay right behind me.
And don't touch anything
without asking.
Believe me, I won't.
The white.
It is time.
How's it coming, Chief?
We're making progress.
Aren't we, Chief?
I'm still trying to locate
the security protocol
interlink.
It shouldn't take much longer.
Well, the sooner the better.
Things are getting
a little crowded up here.
We pledge our loyalties
to the Founders...
We're all Alphas here.
Our loyalty is demonstrated
by our actions, not our words.
All right.
Now...
Miles...
we're lost, aren't we?
Yes, we're lost.
I can draw these circuits
in my sleep.
I've just... never seen them
from this perspective.
Disorientation...
it's one of the effects
of hypoxia...
lack of oxygen.
Need to focus on a landmark.
There.
That large isolinear chip...
number 58966 stroke delta.
What is it?
Julian, there are
two dozen 66/deltas
in the asymmetric
encryption circuits alone.
All right, then what...
what's this here at its base?
Well, that's a four-way
interlink shunt.
So... that would mean
that this chip is?
I don't know!
I told you that they
all look the same to me.
All right, don't look at it.
What?!
Close your eyes.
Use your memory.
Okay. There's a four-way
shunt at the base
of a 58966 stroke delta
isolinear chip...
which is where?
The only four-way
shunt near a 66/delta
is at the base...
of the master
differential relay.
That's got to be it.
So the interlink we want
has to be?
That way.
We've got trouble.
They're cross-checking
the diagnostic protocols.
Has Nog made any progress?
Not yet.
It's stuck.
Which one?
That one.
No, no, no.
You sure?
Oh...
Again.
Julian.
Rub-Rubicon...
m-mission complete.
Oh, I am good.
Come with me.
All of you,
step away from the consoles!
Right now!
Captain, I did it.
I don't know how, but I
released the command codes.
Well done.
What we need now is a diversion
before they go to warp.
Silence!
All the Defiant's
command functions
have been transferred
to Engineering...
but nothing's happening.
Well, maybe the Captain
doesn't realize
he has control of the ship yet.
Or maybe he's in trouble.
The First was called
to the Engine Room
a few minutes ago.
How long has the warp drive
been repaired?
At least one hour...
maybe longer.
And they managed
to conceal it from you?
You ordered me not
to interfere with them.
I also told you
to watch them carefully.
If we had assigned Jem'Hadar
to do the repair, as I said...
I am not interested
in your excuses.
Bring the warp drive on line.
Wait.
Before we activate
the warp drive
we should check
the entire system
for possible sabotage.
That would take hours...
every minute we spend
in Federation space
exposes us to detection
and attack
and I would hate
for your last mission
to end in failure, Elder.
Do it.
And when you have
sufficient engine power
available
bring us to warp 4.
At least we're going
to take them with us.
Secure these four
with the other prisoners.
Dax, upper rail.
I've got him.
This guy is really starting
to get on my nerves.
I have torpedo lock.
Fire!
I'm flooding
all the compartments
except the Engine Room
with anesthezine gas.
Major, get that virus
out of the computer
before someone on the Bridge
engages the warp drive.
Aye, sir.
He should have listened
to you and killed me
when he had the chance.
He was a First.
They don't need... to...
listen.
Obedience brings
victory, and victory is...
Mr. Worf, I think
your wife is here.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
After completing repairs
we were able to return
to the anomaly
and successfully restore
our runabout and its crew
to their normal size.
The surviving Jem'Hadar
have been transferred
to a Federation P.O.W. Camp.
Is that your poem?
Yes.
Bloodwine.
Can I hear it?
It is not finished yet.
Oh, please?
Just the first line?
All right.
But it is my first poem.
I understand.
And I have worked very long
and very hard on this.
I know.
I do not wish to be ridiculed.
I promise.
Very well.
"This is the story
of the little ship
that took a little trip."
What do you think?
It's, uh...
Well, it rhymes.
There's nothing on this padd.
We were just minding
our own business
when suddenly,
right there in front of us
was this immense Jem'Hadar.
He looked as tall
as a Seltan carnosaur.
We were so close
you could see the veins
in his eyeballs throbbing.
We swung around
and ducked behind
the operations console.
I knew we had to get
our sensors back on line
if we were going
to be of any help
to the Captain and the others.
So I said to Julian...
Is there something wrong?
Are you sure you've returned
to your normal size?
Of course.
Why?
Well, you both appear to be
a couple
of centimeters shorter
than you were
the last time I saw you.
A changeling notices
that sort of thing.
I didn't want to say anything
but you do look a little...
on the petite side.
Infirmary.
And they say you don't
have a sense of humor.