Raimus isn't going
to be happy about this.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
Don't you mean
what are we going to do?
Raimus told you
to get the merchandise.
I'll figure something out.
You better.
I said I'll figure it out.
I'm hungry.
Let's have Krellan food.
No. Last time,
that gave me heartburn.
That's because you eat too fast.
I eat when I'm hungry
and when I'm hungry, I eat fast.
If you're not careful
that appetite of yours
is going to kill you someday.
Don't get your hopes up.
Hey!
We're using that com booth.
Go.
Order some nozala sandwiches.
Computer accessed.
Get them to deliver
some extra vilm sauce.
Who should I bill this time?
I don't care who pays for it
just so long as it isn't us.
How about the police?
No.
We billed them
for last night's dinner.
Municipal sanitation?
Do you have their account code?
I will...
in a minute.
Krole!
Don't!
Don't touch him!
He's being spiked!
You all right?
They spiked him.
They spiked him
over a free lunch!
What's this city coming to?
Look at this! Fused.
Too bad.
That's an expensive piece
of hardware.
What are we going to do?
Don't you mean
what is Krole going to do?
I can't go to Raimus
and ask him to pay
for a replacement.
Well, it might not be
as bad as it seems.
Are you saying you can fix it?
Depends.
On what?
How much you're willing to pay.
Do you know who I am?
No.
Well, if you did,
you wouldn't ask that.
Oh. All right.
Who are you?
Listen, Mister, um?
Connelly.
Yeah, I've seen you around here
these last few weeks.
You're always in here
tinkering around
with one piece of junk
or another
which tells me
that things are not going
too well for you.
Now, here's my advice to you.
Give it!
You take these...
you bring them back
tomorrow morning fixed
and polished.
Tomorrow morning it is.
Bilby asked me
to fix these for him.
I'm impressed.
I don't think anyone's
managed to make contact
with the Orion Syndicate
so quickly.
How'd you do it?
I spiked one of his men
while he was interfacing.
That was a risky thing to do.
Well, maybe...
but I had to get noticed.
I want to get this mission
over with and go home.
I realize you didn't
exactly volunteer for this.
Believe me, I wish we hadn't
been forced to turn to someone
outside Starfleet Intelligence
for help.
Me, too.
The Syndicate killed
another one of our undercover
operatives last week.
That makes five
in the last year.
We need you to find out
who their informant
in Starfleet is.
Once you give me the name
I'll put you on the
next transport home.
So, what do you
want me to do now?
Bilby's going to check
into your background.
Whatever he finds will confirm
that you're a fix-it man
down on your luck.
Stick to that cover.
The Syndicate is always looking
for people with your skills.
Bilby offers you more work,
take it.
Get as close to him as possible.
Right.
O'Brien.
Don't take any more
unnecessary risks.
These are dangerous men.
If they find out who you are,
they'll kill you.
- Excuse me, Major. L...
- Major, I'm sorry...
- Go ahead.
- There's something...
- I need a...
All right.
You first, then you.
Hmm.
I need an engineering crew
to run a diagnostic
on the internal
security sensors.
There's been an unusual number
of false alarms lately.
I'll have someone
take a look at it
as soon as possible.
Now, Quark.
There's something's wrong
with the fire-suppression
system in the bar.
Every time
I serve a flaming cocktail
the system engages
and snuffs it out.
I'll put it on the list.
Please do.
You have no idea what people
are willing to pay
for a glass of burning alcohol.
Excuse me.
Major...
Oh, let me guess.
There's a malfunction
in the Infirmary.
How did you know?
Major, there is something wrong
with the turbolift.
I can see that.
We seem to be having
a lot of system glitches.
Happens every time
Chief O'Brien goes away.
I do not understand
why his staff
cannot keep the station running
in his absence.
Must have left
my idiot brother in charge.
The engineering crew is doing
the best they can.
The problem is,
no one knows how the Chief
keeps all this Federation
and Cardassian technology
working together.
We've got to do something.
This can't go on.
Sorry, I can't discuss
the Chief's whereabouts.
I understand that, sir, but...
it's getting ridiculous,
isn't it?
How much longer are
we supposed to put up
with these malfunctions?
You know,
I wouldn't be surprised
if Major Kira or Commander Worf
came in here demanding answers
but you?
It's not your style.
Apparently, it is.
Here I am.
I'm not buying it, Doctor.
You didn't come
in here to complain.
You came here because you are
worried about your friend
and you want me to set
your mind at ease.
I wish I could.
But, if it helps,
I will tell you this.
The Chief can take
care of himself
as well as anyone I know.
You're right about that, sir.
You're right about that.
Did you fix it?
Any feedback?
Feedback gives him a headache.
No, there's no feedback.
Well, we'll see, won't we?
I told you.
Very impressive.
You know, if I was
a suspicious man
I might ask myself
how a tinkerer living
in one room on Jinami Street
managed to fix
such a complicated piece
of hardware so quickly.
Good question.
How do you know where I live?
I know a lot about you...
maybe more than you want me to.
Come with me.
Where are we going?
For a walk.
Have a seat.
Not there.
Chester doesn't like
people sitting in his chair.
Don't touch anything.
Something wrong?
You tell me.
Did you think I brought you here
to kill you?
Why would I kill someone
that can fix things for me?
I guess a man
that's been knocked around
as much as you have is always
expecting the worst, huh?
Well, I've pretty much
had to get used to the idea
that I've got bad luck.
Yeah, that was
a tough break on Dayos IV.
Two years for dealing
in stolen goods?
Well, I didn't know
they were stolen.
I guess I should have asked
the guy I bought them from, huh?
Who's to say
he'd have told you the truth?
Take this, for example.
My employer asked me to get him
three Klingon disruptors.
Did the man I bought them from
tell me they didn't work?
No, he did not.
Have a look.
Ah...
The induction coil
is burned out.
Can you fix it?
Sure.
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
It's going to make my employer
very happy.
What does he want
with Klingon disruptors?
I didn't ask him.
When Raimus tells
you to do something
you just do it.
You hungry?
A little.
Have some cake.
My wife sent it.
No, thanks.
Go ahead.
It's good.
Yeah, she makes it herself.
This is her.
These are my children.
Oh...
great.
Where are they?
They're in New Sydney.
I'd love to have them
here on Farius
but, uh, considering
the business I'm in
it's not a good idea.
You got a family?
No.
You should.
It's the most important thing.
I send them everything.
I pay my fare to Raimus.
The rest goes straight
to my wife.
Your fare?
Yeah, to Raimus every month.
That's the way it works.
He's above me
in the organization.
You do know what organization
I'm referring to, don't you?
I think so.
Good.
Krole and Flith,
the gentlemen you met earlier?
They're below me.
Lucky them.
If you fix
these disruptors for me,
you could be lucky, too.
That's good to know.
Don't misunderstand me.
I'm not promising you anything.
I just need to be sure
that I can trust you first.
Have some more cake.
No, thanks.
I thought you said
you were hungry.
Oh... I'm all right.
What's the matter?
Don't you like my wife's cake?
Oh, I didn't say that.
So, answer me.
Do you like my wife's cake?
To tell you the truth,
it's, uh...
it's a little dry.
You're right, it is.
Had you wondering
which way to jump, didn't I?
You know, Krole and Flith...
they always act as if it's
the best thing they ever tasted.
Whoo.
Hey, what do you make
of that, Chester?
I've found me an honest man.
Must be my lucky day.
The induction coils
you asked for...
courtesy of the Klingon
Ambassador to Farius.
There's a Klingon Ambassador
here?
Gowron mustn't
like him too much.
Do you have any idea why Raimus
wants these disruptors?
No.
Bilby doesn't even know.
Listen, is there, uh...
any way
I could talk to my wife
and let her know I'm all right?
We can't risk it.
I'm sorry.
Better be going.
Flith...
go stand over there.
Why?
I want to see
if he really fixed this.
Very funny.
Contact Raimus.
Tell him we have the disruptors.
Good job.
I'm curious about something.
How did you get ahold
of replacement parts?
Klingon technology
isn't easy to come by.
Well, you know, you...
have to know who to go to.
Hmm. Why don't you enlighten us
in case we need
to procure something else?
I've got a better idea.
Why don't you stay
out of my business?
Tell us where you got the parts.
We can always use
a good contact.
I can't.
Why not?
Well, my supplier would
rather remain anonymous.
I don't care
about your supplier.
I'm asking the question.
I told him I wouldn't.
Where did you get the parts?!
I stole them.
You stole them?
Yeah.
From a warehouse on,
uh, Degora Street.
Well, why didn't
you just say so?
Well, I thought it was
better if you didn't know.
You know, in case the
police caught up with me.
You lied to me
because you didn't want me
to be implicated?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Did you hear that?
He's willing to protect me
if he gets caught.
And try hard as I may,
I can't imagine either of you
willing to do that.
Hey...
you know something?
I think it's time
we did something
about the way you look.
Now, that's more like it.
I think you look great,
Connelly.
What do you think, Krole?
He looks fine.
What are you talking about?
I took him to the same
tailor that I use.
You look fine, too.
I understand...
you've been looking for me.
That's right.
I take it you're in the market
for something.
Well, if I was,
I wouldn't buy anything
from a man that sold me
three useless disruptors.
You know me better than that.
I thought I did.
Those disruptors
were working fine
when I gave them to you.
What happened after that,
I don't know.
Perhaps you dropped them.
I want my money back.
You know I can't do that.
You took delivery.
Let me get something straight.
You're telling me there
was nothing wrong with this
when you sold it to me.
That's correct.
Well, maybe I, uh...
just don't know how to work it.
That must be it.
Well, what do you know?
I figured it out.
Bilby...
Do you know
what would've happened
if I'd given Raimus
three useless disruptors?
He'd have killed me.
If you want your money back...
you can have it!
Why would I want my money back?
It works fine now.
No one takes me for a fool.
I'll do whatever it takes
to protect what I have.
This life...
it isn't for everyone.
Sometimes I wish I could
just get away from it all.
But what would I do with myself?
I'm too old to start over.
Besides, who am I to complain?
The organization's
given me opportunities
I never thought I would have.
Once you're part of it...
once you're accepted...
there's no limit
to what you can do
if you're smart about it.
Smart and careful.
Glad you're paying attention.
I mean, we got people
everywhere...
even on Earth.
Hell, we've even got a man
in Starfleet.
Come on... Starfleet?
That's correct.
Hey, would you do me a favor?
Would you remind me
to pick up a present
for my daughter tomorrow?
She's got a birthday coming up.
Sure thing.
Oh, I want to be there.
Sure hope I can make it.
How did you get
to someone in Starfleet?
It wasn't me.
It was Raimus.
Hey...
do you want to come
to New Sydney with me
meet my family?
Well, if you go, yeah.
How'd he do it?
What's with all the questions?
Nothing. Uh...
I just find it hard to believe
that someone in Starfleet
could be bought.
Makes me wonder
if... he's a double agent.
A double agent?
Well, why would he have
given us the names
of all their
undercover operatives?
Don't worry.
He's the real thing.
Raimus met him when he was
vacationing on Risa last year.
Mr. Starfleet was in charge
of the weather-control system.
Raimus offered him
a very substantial
amount of money
to make it stop raining.
Well, everyone has
their price, I guess.
It's Krole.
Raimus wants to see me.
What, in the middle
of the night?
Hmm...
Bilby.
Raimus.
I brought someone
here to meet you.
I hope I didn't get
you gentlemen out of bed.
Bilby...
who is this?
He's someone I know.
I've never seen him before.
How well do you know him?
I know him.
Then it's settled.
Is that the extent of your
security precautions?
Bilby witnessed for him.
That's all that's necessary.
If you say so.
So...
this is Bilby.
He seems capable enough.
I told you.
I wanted to see for myself.
You procured
the disruptors for us?
That's right.
We're going to ask you
to do something else...
something very important.
You can count on me.
I hope so.
We'll contact you
when it's time.
Don't let me down.
I won't.
Raimus...
My love to your family.
Do you know
what I just did for you?
I think so.
I witnessed for you.
If anything happens...
I'm accountable.
I understand.
Good.
Nice suit.
Bilby got it for me.
That was generous.
He's like that.
I found out who the informer is.
Bilby told me he was in charge
of the weather-control
system on Risa
about a year ago.
It should be easy enough
to figure out who that was.
Yeah.
Is something wrong?
Raimus brought somebody
to meet Bilby.
A Vorta.
You're telling me
that the Orion Syndicate
is working for the Dominion?
Opens up a lot of
possibilities, doesn't it?
None of them very pleasant.
So, do I get to go home now?
Not until you find out
what's going on.
I was afraid
you were going to say that.
All right.
I've accessed
the bank's data files.
I'm reading a three-tier
security protocol.
I see it.
It looks like
an isolation matrix
is protecting the data.
You'll have to bypass
the encryption lockouts.
You make it sound so easy.
Watch out
for recursive dataloops.
You don't want to get
diverted into a backflow.
I'm past the lockouts.
Sweep the matrix.
Give me an access point.
Stand by.
Go!
Initiating data transfer.
Faster.
I'm trying.
I can't hold the matrix
open much longer.
Hurry!
Got it!
Get us out, Krole.
Faster. They're tracing you.
The lockouts are closing.
Move!
Come on!
I'm out.
We did it.
Gentlemen...
we just robbed
the Bank of Bolias.
I was thinking
about opening an account there.
Maybe you should go
with a different bank.
One with better security.
What do you think?
Very nice but, uh...
But what?
I-I don't want to, you know...
What do you mean,
you don't want to?
I brought her here for you.
I appreciate that, but...
But what?
Don't tell me
you don't like girls.
I have a girlfriend.
Since when?
A-a few days...
a week... I don't know.
That's great.
Why didn't you say anything?
I don't know.
It didn't come up.
Listen, I understand
uh, but that's no reason
to hurt this girl's feelings.
Um... we've got some
business to discuss
so, uh, why don't you...
go on ahead home and...
...l'll call you
in a couple of days, okay?
And thanks for coming over.
It was really nice to meet you.
So who is she?
This new girl.
Oh, her name's... Kimiko.
Where'd you meet her?
She works in a flower shop...
arranging flowers.
Well, bring her by sometime.
I'd like to meet her.
Yeah, I will.
A man your age
you should settle down
and have a family.
It's the most important thing.
I don't know
if it's that serious yet.
Well, you let me talk
to her for three minutes.
I'll let you know if
she's the marrying kind.
I can read people right away...
what's in their hearts.
You, for instance.
I saw through you the first
time I laid eyes on you.
Oh, yeah?
I don't think
I've ever seen anyone
so alone in my entire life.
I said to myself
"That man, he doesn't have
a friend in the Quadrant."
Flith and Krole...
they thought you were a snake.
Really?
But I knew better.
When you came back that next day
with the dataport repaired
that's when I knew
we're going to do
great things together.
I'm about to take a step up
in the organization.
Raimus is giving me
an opportunity
and I'm going
to make the best of it.
Everything's changing.
I can feel it.
And it all started
when you came along.
You changed my luck.
I thought you'd changed mine.
I'm going to take care of you.
I don't forget my friends
'cause friends...
they're like family
and nothing's more important.
Nothing.
You're late.
I was beginning to worry.
Sorry.
That's all right.
I imagine the Dominion
is keeping you busy.
No, nothing's
happened with that yet.
I was just doing
something with Bilby.
Anything worth reporting?
We went to the races.
We came out ahead.
I'm glad to hear that you're
enjoying your assignment.
Well, you told me
to get close to him.
He said he wanted to go;
I went with him.
There's no need to explain.
I've been undercover.
Bilby's witnessed for me.
Sounds like you've really
got your hooks into him.
What's going to happen to him
when you pull me out?
That's nothing that you need
to think about.
They're going to kill him,
aren't they?
Listen, Bilby chose this life.
Whatever happens to him
is his fault
not yours.
Besides, if he's lucky,
we'll get to him
before they do.
He'll be safe
in a Federation prison.
Just help us build a good case
against him.
Right.
Good morning, Graife.
Raimus.
I didn't know you were coming.
I can see that.
Well, let me get you something.
Graife, make us
a strong pot of...
Bilby, not right now.
This isn't a social visit.
Which one is it?
Wait. Don't tell me.
Let me see if I can guess.
They say you can tell a traitor
by looking in his eyes.
Do you think that's true, Bilby?
I wouldn't know.
Raimus, what's this all about?
What does it look like?
If you ask me, none of them
look particularly trustworthy.
Raimus...
Not now.
But...
I said not now.
Him.
I've been saying so all along!
Raimus, this is crazy.
He doesn't know
what he's talking about.
He was going
to be my second guess.
W-what did he do?
Let's just say he conducted
some business on the side
and neglected to pay his fare.
I see.
It's a good thing
you never witnessed for him
or you'd be lying there, too,
Bilby.
Yeah.
Well, now that that's
out of the way
shall we discuss
the matter at hand?
We mentioned we might ask you
to do something for us.
Yeah, whatever you need.
Mmm. So accommodating.
He reminds me of a Jem'Hadar.
We want you to assassinate
the Klingon Ambassador
to Farius.
- All right.
- And you'll
use the disruptors you procured
earlier.
You want it to look like he was
killed by a rival House.
Connelly!
It's all right.
Very astute.
Do you know much about
political affairs?
Not really.
Well, then, allow me
to enlighten you.
The Ambassador has been
advocating that the Klingons
break off their alliance
with the Federation
and concentrate on defending
the Empire against the Dominion.
Chancellor Gowron,
on the other hand
is adamantly committed
to the Alliance.
You're going to making it look
like Gowron ordered
the assassination.
Exactly.
The Ambassador will be seen
as a martyr
and his cause
will gain strength.
If all goes well
the Klingons will retreat
into their own territory
and then,
all we'll have to deal with
is the Federation.
Makes sense.
I'm glad you think so.
Needless to say,
it is very important
that the Dominion's part in this
remain secret.
If something goes wrong
and you're captured...
you never met our friend here.
I understand.
I knew I could count on you.
I never realized
how much the Dominion
and the Orion Syndicate
have in common.
It seems
that in both organizations...
Loyalty is everything.
How are they planning
to get past
the Embassy's security?
Bilby asked me the same thing.
I figured out a way
to interrupt the power grid
for a few seconds.
Bilby and his men
will be able to beam in
before the backup
generator kicks in.
When is this supposed to happen?
Tonight.
I'll contact the Klingons,
so they can be ready for them.
What are you talking about?
If the Klingons get their hands
on Bilby and his men
they'll kill them.
That's not really our business,
is it?
You're setting them up
to be murdered?
You have things backwards.
Bilby and his friends
are the ones
that murder people, not us.
We just get Klingons
to do it for us.
All I'm doing is following
procedures
and warning our allies
about a possible
assassination attempt.
What happens after that
is not my concern
but believe me,
if the Klingons go after Raimus
and the rest
of the Orion Syndicate
I won't shed any tears.
I'm sure you won't.
Miles...
listen to me.
You've lost perspective.
You're starting to sympathize
with these people.
It's good
that we're pulling you out.
Pulling me out?
We're putting you
on the next transport home.
Your assignment's over.
You told me we were going
to make a case against Bilby.
You told me
he was going to prison!
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to mislead you
but you were starting to waver.
I needed to keep you on track.
Come on.
Let's get you home.
Chadwick.
There you go, Chester.
Who could that be?
Did you come to see me off?
We need to talk.
Have to wait.
I was just leaving.
You can't go.
What are you talking about?
Look, just
trust me.
You can't go.
Why not?
It's a trap.
Listen to me!
The Klingons know
what you're planning to do.
That's impossible.
Someone traced my signal
when I accessed the power grid.
I saw you access the grid.
You cut off the trace.
No, they just made me
think I had.
You're panicking.
Try not to worry so much.
You're the one
who should be worried.
Do you have any idea
what the Klingons
will do to you
when they catch you?
They're not going to catch me.
Yes, they will.
Starfleet Intelligence
will warn them you're coming.
How do you know that?
I suppose you work for them.
What if I said I did?
Very good. You had me.
I mean, just for a minute there
I actually thought that you
were working for Starfleet.
I am.
Come on.
That's enough.
You had me. I admit it.
I am working for Starfleet.
That's enough! I said
I don't want to hear that!
Do you understand me?
I don't want to hear that.
Why'd you have to come here?
Why'd you have to tell me that?
I couldn't just let you go.
The Klingons will kill you.
I'm dead already.
Can't you see that?
I witnessed for you.
Do you have any idea
what that means?
What if I get you off Farius?
Find you a place to hide?
There's no hiding
from the Syndicate.
You know that.
Well, then turn yourself in.
You'll be safe in prison.
No! They'd go after my family!
They'd make an example of me.
Raimus may leave them alone
if he thinks that I died
not knowing about you.
But you can't
just let them kill you.
What choice do I have?
How did I let this happen?
I should have known.
You were too good to be true.
I wanted so much to believe
that my luck had changed
I didn't see it.
I never meant
for this to happen.
I wasn't after you.
I was just trying to find out
how the Syndicate
compromised Starfleet.
I wasn't even your target.
I suppose
I'm not important enough.
I've always known something
like this might happen.
The smart thing would be
to kill you.
But I guess I've already
proved...
I'm not too smart.
I'm sorry, Bilby.
You'll never know
how little comfort that is.
If it's not too much trouble
will you make sure
Chester is looked after?
Be good.
Do you mind
if I ask you something?
Back home...
wherever that is...
do you have a family?
Yeah.
Good.
It's the most important thing.
I'll never forget
the look on his face
when he found out
who I really was.
Well, you took an enormous risk
by telling him.
He could have killed you.
I knew he wouldn't.
Well, all I can say
is that you're lucky
that Chadwick decided not
to put everything in his report.
Julian, you don't understand
what I'm trying to tell you.
Bilby trusted me.
He put his life in my hands,
and...
I killed him
just as surely as if I'd
pulled that trigger myself.
That's not fair,
and you know it.
You did what you had to do...
your duty.
Is that what I'm supposed
to tell myself?
It is the truth.
Look, I'm sorry that I don't
have all the answers.
All I know for sure
is that I'm glad you're back.