Sell at 20.
Is that a joke?
Do I look like I'm joking?
Evade.
She has him.
-She's down 50 strips.
-Not for long.
What makes you so sure?
Well, Jadzia's playing a very deep game.
Her strategy will become
apparent any moment now.
I see.
You have absolutely no idea
how this game is played, do you?
-No.
-( chuckles )
But I have developed
a new appreciation for it.
-Oh? Since when?
-Since I married a Tongo player.
But one thing I am certain about--
She will defeat the Ferengi bartender.
I don't know about that.
Quark's on a roll.
In the last month,
he's won 206 straight games.
Would you care to make
a wager on the outcome?
Oh, I wouldn't want to bet
against a man's wife.
-Well, if you are afraid--
-Name your stakes.
One bottle of bloodwine
against one bottle of scotch whiskey.
Done.
A sale at 50 and a purchase at 100.
Pretty big talk for
a lady who's lost 50 strips.
Are you afraid I can't cover my bets?
Perish the thought!
I just hate to kick
somebody when they're down.
I'll buy at 100... and confront.
Well, if you're gonna kick me,
I'm gonna have to kick back.
QUARK: unbelievable.
( exclaims in native langauge )
I like my bloodwine
very young and very sweet.
-Is he a friend of yours?
-Just a fan.
I'm afraid I'm going to have
to disappoint all your fans.
A full consortium?
207.
A single malt,
preferably something from the highlands.
I will need some time.
Oh, your credit's good.
Whoo, 207 straight.
QUARK: 36 strips of gold press latinum.
-Did you lose a bet?
-It is of no consequence.
I'm sorry about that.
I would rather lose a bet on you
than win on someone else.
Ooh, good response.
Are you still running
that drill tomorrow afternoon?
I was planning to. Why?
Because I wanted to recalibrate
the external sensors
before the night watch comes on duty.
We should be done by 1600 hours.
Well, I think that'll work.
Oh, the Sutherland is going to
be here the day after tomorrow and...
-You were saying?
-Nothing.
I don't feel like talking anymore.
-( beep )
-Kira to Worf.
Worf here.
KIRA: Sorry to bother you, Commander,
but I need to see you and Jadzia
in the Captain's office, immediately.
We're on our way.
Jadzia... Get up.
I'm coming!
Hey!
We don't have a lot of time,
so I'll get right to it.
For the last two months,
Starfleet has been receiving
military intelligence
from a Cardassian operative.
That operative has now sent
an emergency signal
indicating he needs to speak to someone
in a face-to-face conversation.
In 13 hours,
he'll beam an encrypted
subspace transmission
to these coordinates in the badlands.
Who is the operative?
Intelligence told me that
his name is Lasaran,
But that's all they'll say about him.
They did emphasize several times that
he is very important to them
and that we should send someone
to the badlands as soon as possible.
So, with the Defiant gone,
and most of the runabouts off on exercises
with the Ninth Fleet...
We just volunteered for
a trip to the badlands.
Afraid so.
The Shenandoah's prepped
and ready to go on landing pad "A."
Good luck.
-No.
-No?
No, I'm not going to spend two weeks
hiking across Vulcan's forge
in the middle of their summer.
I thought you always
wanted to see the forge.
See it, yes. Honeymoon there, no.
Well, there's a mountain-climbing
expedition on Andor
that caught my attention.
Worf... My love...
Let me make this very clear.
I do not want to spend my honeymoon
climbing, hiking, sweating, bleeding,
or suffering in any way.
-All right, what do you want?
-Room service.
-Room service?
I want to be pampered.
I want a staff to cater to our every whim.
I want to be embarrassed
by the size of our room.
I want a balcony with a view
that would make you want
to break down and cry
from the sheer beauty of it all.
And I don't want to spend
one moment of our honeymoon
suffering from anything
except guilt about
our complete self-indulgence.
Risa.
Not this time.
Welcome to Casperia Prime,
the vacation capital
of the Horvarian cluster.
You have been planning this all along.
Well, it seemed fair.
You did plan the wedding.
Very well. Room service.
-Really?
-Really.
Well, that was easy.
Did you want to fight over it?
No. It's just...
I didn't expect you
to surrender so quickly.
-Surrender?
-Bad word.
-Very bad.
-OK.
But you have to admit you've been
unusually...accommodating lately.
What is wrong with that?
Nothing. It's just...
Unusual.
Are you feeling all right?
I am a married man.
I have to make certain...
adjustments in my lifestyle.
Adjustments?
Worf, you're practically easygoing.
What's next, a sense of humor?
I have a sense of humor.
On the Enterprise,
I was considered to be quite amusing.
Well, that must've been one dull ship.
That is a joke!
I get it.
It is not funny, but I get it.
I don't know if I can
get used to the new you.
It's kind of eerie.
Your problem is
you cannot accept change.
-I can't accept change?
-That is correct.
Oh, you've got to be kidding.
I've changed bodies six times, Worf.
Yes, but you are still
very set in your ways.
And look who's talking.
Well, I do not have to sleep
on the same side of the bed every night,
or brush my hair exactly 50 strokes
every night,
or eat the same thing
for breakfast every day,
or read the last page of the book
before the beginning,
-or lift up--
-I get the point.
I don't know how you can live
with someone so monotonous.
It is not easy.
That was a joke.
This is going to be
a very, very long trip.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You're not dressed.
-Is it time?
-1700 on the dot.
We have the holosuite
for the next three hours,
and we're going to
need every minute of it.
Three British agents have disappeared
in West Berlin.
Now, M.I. Five suspect
the Soviets were involved of course.
However, the Americans
have intercepted a, uh...
What are you doing with a Tongo wheel?
I'm brushing up on my game.
-You play Tongo?
-Sure.
Well, I used to.
That is, I played the game once,
a long time ago,
with a Ferengi privateer
and a Romulan mercenary.
Fascinating.
Anyway, the Americans have intercepted
a series of messages from Istanbul
to a remote island in the South Pacific
-which might indicate--
-Let's play a hand.
Miles...
-Just one hand.
-Why?
I need the practice.
( sighs )
I want to beat Quark.
Good luck.
Luck has nothing to do with it.
Tongo is a game of strategy
and calculated risk.
I don't even know the rules.
Well, here.
All right, let's play. I'll deal.
WORF: Shenandoah log: Stardate 51597.2.
We have arrived
at the designated coordinates
near the badlands and are
awaiting the transmission from Lasaran.
JADZIA: This is it.
A very sophisticated encryption matrix.
Whoever he is, he's good.
Who are you?
I'm Commander Worf. This is Commander Dax.
Starfleet Intelligence has sent us here
to receive your transmission.
A Klingon.
Why did they have to send a Klingon?
I'm a Trill.
Does that make you feel any better?
-Are you trying to be funny?
-Oh, not at all. He's the funny one.
-What is it you want?
-We'll get to that in a minute.
First, I have something
that you want, badly...
Information on the Founders.
I know how many of them
there are in the Alpha Quadrant,
where they are, and what they're doing.
-We're listening.
-I'm sure you are.
Now let's talk about what I want.
I want out, now.
You want to defect.
The Vorta advisor here
is getting suspicious...
Asking questions,
making a lot of routine
security checks in my section.
I can't stay here any longer.
WORF: Very well.
We will relay your message
to Starfleet Intelligence
and they will arrange to bring you out.
I can't wait for them
to make arrangements.
In 15 minutes, I am leaving here
for the Dominion base on Soukara,
and I have a feeling
this is going to be the last time
that they let me leave Cardassia Prime.
So, I need to take advantage
of this opportunity.
Soukara is inside
Dominion-controlled space.
It will not be easy to make a rendezvous
near that planet without being detected.
Don't work your brain too hard, Klingon.
I've taken care of everything.
Three days from now
at exactly 1730 hours local time,
I will leave the base
and walk into the jungle.
It'll be at least two days
before they know I'm missing.
All you have to do
is get me off the planet.
Now, there are transporter scramblers
protecting Soukara
so you can't beam me aboard your ship.
You're going to have to land
and meet me at a rendezvous point on foot.
I am sending you all
the information you'll need
to avoid the Dominion sensors
on the ground.
Follow my instructions.
Meet me at this rendezvous point
and have a ship waiting.
We've got the information.
It looks pretty thorough.
We will need time to study these plans.
You haven't been listening.
I don't have time.
Once I leave here,
I can't contact you again.
I have to know if you're
going to be there or not,
and I have to know now!
We will be there.
How far I've fallen... ( sighs )
Risking my life on the word of a Klingon.
Three days. Don't be late.
All right.
I'll buy at 30 with sales at 35.
Buy at 35, sell at 150
and index the margin at 10%.
-Index the margin?
-Miles, give it up.
-This just isn't your game.
-We'll see about that.
( sighs )
Evade.
Do you realize
that Quark has won
207 straight games of Tongo?
So?
So, someone has to beat him.
And that someone is you?
Why not?
Well, for one thing, you can't play Tongo.
Confront.
( groans ) Damn!
-Had enough?
-Not by a long shot.
Miles, at this rate,
it's going to take you another 20 years
to be ready to take on Quark.
One more.
( sighs ) Why are you
so determined to beat him?
-It's the challenge.
-A challenge?
Isn't it enough?
I mean, why do you think
I became an engineer, eh?
The challenge.
What do you think's kept me
kayaking down the same river
week after week for the last seven years?
The challenge.
Why would I keep playing darts
against somebody
with a genetically engineered
hand/eye coordination, huh?
-The challenge.
-Exactly.
I have to do something
to keep my mind off the fact
that Keiko's been away
for the last six months.
Hold on.
Maybe I can't beat Quark...
But you can.
You and that genetically
engineered brain of yours.
Me? I've only just learned
how to play the game.
Yeah, in about 10 seconds flat!
We can do it, Julian.
We can beat him.
"We"?
You're talking about me.
Yeah, well, you're good at calculation
but a little weak on strategy.
-I'll be your coach.
-No, thank you.
Think of it as a challenge.
That's your obsession, Miles, not mine.
Do it for the latinum.
Nice try.
Do it for the satisfaction
of the look on Quark's face
when he's beaten at a game of Tongo
by a lowly "hu-man."
Deal the cards.
We are approaching the Soukara system.
Stand by to bring us out of warp.
Now.
There is an asteroid field directly ahead.
That's what we want.
The Dominion's sensor grid
in the system has three gaps
and they're all in that asteroid field.
JADZIA: Want me to slow down?
No, unless you think you should.
Not at all. In fact, we could go faster.
By all means.
Ooh! A man after my own heart.
Most impressive.
Nothing that any
300-year-old pilot couldn't do.
We are being scanned from the surface.
JADZIA: Taking evasive maneuvers.
Did they get a fix on us?
WORF: I do not think so.
JADZIA: Good. We've come too long a way
just to get shot down.
If you take the helm,
I'll scan the surface for a landing site.
There's the base...
The rendezvous point...
And the Dominion sensor perimeter.
There's a valley about 20 kilometers
north of the rendezvous point.
It's a long way to go
on foot in the jungle,
but I don't think we can risk taking
the ship any closer to their sensors.
Agreed.
We have less than two days
to reach the rendezvous point.
About 10 kilometers a day,
that shouldn't be too bad.
Do not underestimate the task ahead.
We still have to penetrate the sensor grid
and avoid the Dominion patrols.
( sighs ) I know,
find a man in the middle
of an alien jungle,
then walk him out without getting caught.
Piece of cake.
-Ready?
-After you.
OK.
Go to 25 joules.
WORF: 25 joules.
Done.
That's it. We're linked.
Here, check my work.
Dominion encryption lockouts bypassed,
tricorder link to their sensor grids,
life signs masked.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
Of course, our tricorders
will be useless from now on.
There you go again,
looking for the cloud
in the silver lining.
I am not complaining.
I look forward to walking
through the jungle
without a map
and no idea of what lies ahead.
Well, the funny thing is you probably are.
This is a Ferengi-only game, gentlemen.
You let Dax play.
She's an exception, the only exception.
You're afraid I'll clean you out.
I'm afraid you'll embarrass yourself
and ruin the game for the rest of us.
I think I can keep up.
The question is, can you keep up with me?
Don't try and scare me
with that genetically engineered
intellect of yours, Doctor.
Tongo is more than just number crunching.
They have yet to create the computer
that can master this game.
Then you shouldn't have
anything to worry about.
You realize we are not playing for drinks.
This is a high stakes game.
We came to play.
Gentlemen?
( grunting )
All right.
The buy-in is five strips,
and you're dealing.
You better get off to a fast start.
They won't know what hit them.
Buy at 300, sell at 350.
You're a quick study, Doctor.
I'll give you that.
You mean quick for a "hu-man,"
don't you, Quark?
I would never say anything
so distasteful during a game.
No, you'd wait until it was over.
Of course.
Evade.
Dax was a quick study too.
She told me it only took her two weeks
to win her first match.
That's practically unheard of.
Dax specializes in the unexpected.
Still buying at 300, selling at four.
I'd like to index the margin at 20%.
Interesting.
She certainly did the unexpected
when she married Commander Boring.
That's for sure.
When they first started seeing each other,
I thought,
"This can't last. I give it two months."
I'll buy at 400...
And sell at five.
I had the same thought.
Although, to tell you the truth,
I only gave it a month.
Confront.
She's a real heart-breaker, that one.
That she is.
Leverage the buy-in and sell at 550.
You know...
You go through a lot of ups and downs
in my business.
There are days when the profits are down,
and the customers are scarce,
and you think you'll never see
another strip of latinum again,
And then, Jadzia comes in...
And flashes that smile of hers.
Suddenly things
don't seem so bad after all.
I know exactly what you mean.
You know,
sometimes she walks past the infirmary,
and all she has to do is wink,
and somehow, that...
makes my whole day look a little brighter.
Focus, Julian. Focus.
Shh!
I'll, uh, buy that 550, and...
Index the exchange at 10.
And now she's married.
Married.
Out of reach.
I'm converting my reserves...
And selling at 600.
You know what's really sad?
What really keeps me awake at night?
She's out of reach because we let her go.
Yes, I suppose so...
But some things just weren't meant to be.
Evade.
Julian!
Are you sure you want to--
Chief! Please. You know the rules.
No coaching during a round.
You're probably right.
But what if that's
a convenient rationalization?
What if deep down in our heart of hearts,
we both know she's something unique...
Something we may never see again,
a chance at true happiness?
And we let her slip through our fingers.
What if 50 years from now
we each look back
and say, "What a fool I was"?
Confront.
Doctor?
Hmm?
Confront.
Oh.
Sorry. Um...
Full consortium.
Total monopoly.
-What?
-( Ferengis snickering )
You seem to be out of money.
Miles?
We're busted.
Thanks for the game.
Welcome back anytime.
BASHIR: Wait.
Quark, did you really mean all that
about Dax...
Being my one last chance
for true happiness?
Doctor, you don't expect me
to show you all my cards, do you?
( money rattling )
( sighs ) You lost.
What ever happened to "we"?
We weren't mooning over lost love
with a Ferengi holding a total monopoly.
You mean all that about Dax
was meant to distract me?
Obviously.
I can't believe I let him get to me.
Ah. Well... Not your fault.
Genetically engineered or not,
you're still "hu-man."
( rueful chuckling ) I guess.
-Let's get a drink.
-( groaning )
( device humming )
Ow!
( shivering )
Oh, let's not stand on pride, shall we?
Trills don't like the heat
and Klingons don't like the cold.
There's no shame in admitting it.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, how are you enjoying your honeymoon?
Are you suffering enough?
Almost.
Is there anything I can get for you?
More pain.
Less cold.
( laughing )
I don't know why that's funny, but it is.
( animal howling )
Mating call?
500 meters.
That way.
( howling )
Well, that didn't take long.
Less than 300 meters.
( howling )
( sighs ) Another happy couple.
When I was a boy,
my father used to take my brother and me
on camping trips in the Ural mountains.
Every night, we would listen to the wolves
howling in the distance.
Nikolai was afraid of them,
but I would lay in my tent for hours,
just listening.
I remember being seized by the urge
to just rip off my clothes
and run into the night
and live in the forest,
and become something... wild.
( howling )
He must have been rejected.
He's moving away.
( howling and growling )
She's not happy.
( twig snaps )
( growling )
What? They're getting further away,
aren't they?
Yes, but it's because
something is coming.
And it is close.
( brush rustling )
( device beeping )
( yelling and grunting )
( strangled gurgling yell )
( groaning )
Jadzia!
( gasping )
Lie still.
I think I can do that.
( groaning )
Can I have the good news first?
No vital organs were damaged.
Now the bad news?
The disruptor burst
left an anti-coagulant in your system.
So you can't stop the bleeding?
No.
Well, I must not have taken
the whole burst.
I'm not hemorrhaging that bad yet.
Just keep me pumped full of painkillers,
and let's be on our way.
Moving could make the bleeding worse.
Staying here isn't an option.
Someone's going to come looking for them
when they don't check in,
and I'd rather take my chances on foot.
You ready?
-You ready?
-Ready.
Let's go.
( grunting )
( groans softly )
We are still 12 kilometers
from the rendezvous point.
And only 20 hours left.
Well, I guess it's time
we stop having so much fun
and pick up the pace, huh?
Oh, more plasma.
No, thanks. I'm full. ( chuckles weakly )
Your blood pressure
has dropped another 20%.
Love that bedside manner.
You know, you should have been a doctor?
Your bandage will need to be changed soon.
Well, I think I'd like a blue
chiffon bandage this time,
maybe some rhinestones.
Something with a little pizazz.
This is no joking matter.
You are seriously injured,
and we have
a great deal of terrain to cover.
Just trying to lighten the mood.
This is neither the time nor the place.
What happened to that new Worf?
You know, the one with the sense of humor?
That was a mistake.
Oh, what is that supposed to mean?
It means if I had
not been joking with you,
I would not have allowed
the Jem'Hadar to get so close.
( sighs ) So this is all my fault.
No.
It is mine.
I was trying to be something I am not.
By letting down my guard,
by ignoring my duty,
I allowed my wife to be injured,
and I put the entire mission in jeopardy.
It will not happen again.
That's not what happened.
-Without our tricorders, there's no way--
-I do not wish to debate this.
We have a long way to go
and very little time.
Fine. Let's go.
( grunts )
( device beeping )
Ready?
( softly ) Yeah.
( groaning )
( groans )
Hypo.
( groaning )
There. Good as new.
I have to change your dressing.
That's four bandages in two hours.
That's got to be some kind of record.
Oh, sorry. I forgot the new rules.
Nothing funny.
Got to be serious.
Life and death.
We've got a job to do.
Jadzia, I know you are tired,
but we have to cover three kilometers
before nightfall. Can you do it?
As long as you got those painkillers,
I'll follow you
through the gates of hell, sir.
Hmm...
Oh, that was almost a smile.
When this mission is over,
I will smile all you want.
Oh, you promise?
I promise.
Then let's finish this mission
and get out of here.
( both grunt )
Whoa.
( groans )
That's all right, I can stand.
Just help me get my balance.
Help me balance.
Or maybe not.
( gasps )
( grunting )
( beeping )
Let me guess. Things aren't looking up.
There's been another drop
in your blood pressure.
And your neural E.D.L. readings
are erratic.
So what's your prescription, doc?
Surgery... at a Starbase.
Could I get a second opinion?
Worf, you have to go on without me...
And I know that.
I understand.
My duty requires
that I complete the mission
regardless of my personal feelings.
Absolutely.
You're a Starfleet officer.
So am I, and I understand.
The information Lasaran has could be
potentially invaluable to the war effort.
You don't have to explain to me.
I'm hurt. You're not.
And there's a job to be done.
I will be back tomorrow night.
Don't worry.
I'm not going anywhere.
I can have you in the stasis chamber
on the runabout in 45 hours.
No problem.
I will leave the med kit.
Scan yourself with the tricorder
every half hour.
The plasma hypospray will be set--
I took basic first aid.
I know what I have to do.
Worf.
It's been a great two months, hasn't it?
Yes.
Jadzia, I just want to tell you how--
( whispers ) Just kiss me and go.
( sobbing )
( heart beating )
( beating louder )
( sighs )
What's the word?
She is still in surgery,
but Dr. Bashir is hopeful
she will make a full recovery.
Lasaran's dead.
Starfleet intelligence
intercepted a transmission
saying that he'd been killed
trying to reenter the base at Soukara.
Could you have made the rendezvous?
Yes.
-But yet you turned back to save Jadzia.
-Yes.
Were you aware that
the information that man had
could have saved millions of lives?
Yes.
So what happened?
-You may not understand.
-Try me, sir.
You were at my wedding.
You heard the story
of the first two Klingon hearts
and how nothing could stand against them
and how they even destroyed
the Gods that had created them.
I have heard that story since I was a boy,
but I never understood it...
I mean really understood it...
Until I was standing in the jungle
with my heart pounding in my chest,
and I found that even I could
not stand against my own heart.
I had to go back.
And it did not matter
what Starfleet thought,
or what the consequences were.
She was my wife and I could not leave her.
As your captain,
it is my duty to inform you
that you made the wrong choice.
I don't think Starfleet will file
any formal charges.
Even a secret court-martial
would run the risk
of revealing too much about
their intelligence operations.
But this will go into your service record.
And to be completely honest,
you probably won't be offered
a command on your own after this.
I understand.
I've also issued new orders.
You and Jadzia are not
to be assigned to a mission
on your own ever again.
And one last thing.
As a man who had a wife...
If Jennifer had been
lying in that clearing...
I wouldn't have left her either.
( door opens )
Hey.
( whispers ) I know you.
We have met.
Ah, you're joking again.
That's a good sign.
Did you make the rendezvous?
No.
( softly) I could not leave you there.
Not for Lasaran, not for the mission,
not for anything else.
Lasaran?
Dead.
Are you in trouble?
I have been in trouble before.
I'm sorry.
I should have kept going.
You have nothing to be sorry about.
I know how much your career means to you.
You come first.
Before career, before duty,
before anything.
I do not regret what I did,
and I would do it again.
I don't know what to say.
You could say,
"Thank you for saving my life."
Thank you for saving my life.
And you could say,
"I would do the same for you, Worf."
Well... I'd have to think about that.
My career is very important to me,
you know.
( sighs )
And you could say, "I love you."
I love you.
And I love you.