The Saratoga put in
this morning.
We are not having another party.
I promise, not more
than 50 or 60...
I can see it now.
200 people jammed
into our quarters... eating
drinking, laughing.
Sounds awful.
What if I promise
absolutely no laughing?
No, I mean it.
You won't see a single
smile the entire evening.
It'll be the grimmest party
you've ever been to.
When do you want
to have this party?
Next week.
And I was thinking
maybe this evening
should have... a theme.
What kind of theme?
What if everyone came as
their favorite Klingon?
Bad idea.
Commander,
your holosuite is ready.
Good.
Have fun exercising.
No party?
I came this close.
Thank you, Quark.
Don't mention it, Major.
Glad to be of help.
Bajoran lilacs.
Is there something going on
between the two of you
that I don't know about?
Oh, don't be disgusting.
I ordered them for myself.
Well, that's nice.
I thought you
didn't like flowers.
I don't.
I'm confused.
Jadzia, there's
such a thing as privacy.
Not between friends.
It's my mother's birthday.
She would've been 60 today
and my father always said
that these were her favorite.
That's a nice way
to remember your mother.
I wish I did remember her.
I was only three
when she died
at the refugee center.
Well, I bet
she'd be proud of you
and what you've done
with your life.
Hmm. I'd like to think so.
I've always been proud of her.
My father always said...
she was the bravest woman
he ever met.
Major Kira, you have
an incoming transmission.
From whom?
Unable to identify.
Oh...
Put it through.
Ah, Major, there you are.
I'm sorry to wake you.
What the hell
do you want, Dukat?
Oh, don't bother, Major.
I guarantee you won't be able
to trace this transmission.
Well, then, why don't you
just tell me where you are?
Because that's not why I called.
I want to help you, Major,
the way Captain Sisko helped me.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Captain Sisko
gave me the clarity
to see beyond the lies...
the self-deceptions
that were controlling my life.
He helped me to see
the truth about myself
and now, I'm going to do
the same for you.
And what better day to do it
than on your mother's birthday.
Was that supposed to upset me?
That you know
it's my mother's birthday?
She was a striking woman,
your mother...
although when we first met
she was very self-conscious
about that scar
along the side of her face.
She used to try to cover it up
with a strand of hair.
Nice try, Dukat...
but you never knew my mother.
She died in the...
The Singha refugee center?
I'm afraid not, Major.
That was something
your father told you
because he couldn't bear
to face the truth.
What truth?
That your mother left him...
to be with me.
Oh, you're lying.
Your mother and I were lovers
almost from the moment we met.
And we remained lovers
until the day she died.
I have had enough of this.
I see you have lilacs
on your nightstand.
Your mother
would've been touched.
She loved Bajoran lilacs.
There.
I told you the truth
was liberating, Major.
Now, don't you feel better?
I do.
Computer, locate
Cardassian occupation files
Singha refugee center.
Find and display Bajoran
identity profile: Kira Meru.
You're just going to have
to take my word for it.
The Battle of the Alamo
would make
a hell of a holosuite program.
All right, all right.
Let me get this straight
because I...
There are 200 of us
trapped inside some crumbling
old mission or whatever
surrounded
by 2,000 enemy troops.
Is that right?
That's right.
Do we win?
No, we lose.
Why do you want
to play a program
where we lose?
Well, you're missing the point.
There's nothing more noble
than a heroic defeat,
especially against
overwhelming odds.
In life maybe
but not in the holosuite.
Chief, you were supposed
to have finished recalibrating
those induction modulators
yesterday.
Yeah, we had a bit of a problem
replacing some of the coil...
Save the excuses.
I want it done within the hour.
Doctor, is there a reason
for your visit?
What?
Actually, Miles and I were...
Thought not.
We're on duty here
if you don't mind.
I don't want to interfere.
Well, all right, everyone,
we're not at the Replimat.
We're not here
to drink raktajinos
and catch up
on the latest gossip.
Let's get to work.
Odo, I've just been informed
of the increased criminal
activity on the Promenade.
It's not as bad
as it sounds, Major.
We're talking about
a few incidents of petty theft.
I've already assigned
two deputies.
I'd prefer that you handle
the matter yourself.
If you think it's necessary.
I do.
And make sure that you keep me
informed of your progress.
Of course.
Is there something else
on your mind?
Meaning what?
Meaning I talked
with Dr. Bashir.
He told me
that you seemed irritable.
I see he's not exaggerating.
Would you care to tell me
what's bothering you?
I appreciate the offer, Odo
but I don't think talking
about it is going to help.
Sounds serious.
It is.
Well, if you won't talk about it
perhaps you should consider
doing something about it.
A transmission from Gul Dukat?
This is the first
I've heard of it.
That's because
I didn't report it.
Why not?
It was of a personal nature.
I tried to trace the signal,
but...
What did he want?
He said he knew my mother,
that they were lovers.
You don't believe him, do you?
He knew certain things
about her.
Personal things.
Well, Gul Dukat is
a very resourceful man.
I'm sure he knows
a lot about your family...
about all of our families.
I keep trying to tell myself
that, but I need to know.
That may not be possible, Major.
There is a way.
I can visit
the temple of lponu on Bajor
and consult the Orb of Time.
Excuse me?
I need to know the truth.
Let me get this straight.
You want to travel
back in time
to see if Gul Dukat
and your mother were lovers.
That's right.
Major, the Federation
has very strict
regulations concern...
This has nothing to do
with the Federation.
I need your help
as the Emissary,
not a Starfleet Captain.
The Emissary can see to it
that I am allowed access
to the Orb.
After that,
it's up to the Prophets.
If they feel
that my request is worthy
they'll send me
where I need to go.
If not, I've made a trip
to Bajor for nothing.
And if they do send you back?
What then?
What makes you so sure
you won't interfere
with the timeline?
The Prophets will be guiding me.
Nothing will happen
without their blessings.
Please, Emissary.
Please...
let me seek the will
of the Prophets.
Thank you.
Meru, I found Nerys.
Where was she?
Wandering over there,
scrounging for food.
Come here, sweetie,
beside me, here.
Is that all?
That's barely half a cup.
They've cut everyone's rations.
It's not enough.
How do they expect us
to survive?
The Cardassians don't care
whether or not we survive.
They won't be happy
until we're all dead.
Come here, sweetie, come here.
Have some soup.
Excuse me.
That soup... it's ours.
What are you talking about?
My wife stood in line
all day to get it.
If you think you can just...
Just... what?
It's for the children.
They're hungry.
We are all hungry.
That's right, we are.
And hunger can make people
do stupid things.
Like what you're doing now.
Cardassians are the enemy.
We shouldn't be
fighting amongst ourselves.
We should be trying
to help each other.
That's what we were doing...
helping ourselves to some soup.
Hey, you want soup
you go stand in line
like everyone else.
We may have to take orders
from the spoonheads
but we don't have
to take them from you!
Oh, thank you.
I wish we could repay
your kindness somehow,
but we have so little food.
That's all right;
I'm not hungry.
Can't remember the last time
I met a Bajoran
who wasn't hungry.
I'm Kira Meru.
I'm...
just glad I could help.
And this is my husband
Taban, my son, Reon
my son, Pohl,
and my daughter, Nerys.
They're beautiful.
Mommy. Mommy.
What is it, honey?
What is it?
What? Tell me.
She wants to know
what your name is.
Me?
I'm Luma Rahl.
It's nice to meet you, Nerys.
Attention!
The new Cardassian
Ore Processing Center
orbiting Bajor is
nearing completion.
The Cardassian troops
stationed there
will require "comfort women"
to make their tour of duty
less... stressful.
Her.
- No!
From now on, you'll
receive extra rations
of food and medicine...
courtesy of our Prefect,
Gul Dukat.
Her.
No!
And her.
But my children...
Your children will eat better
than they have any right to.
Meru!
Mommy!
I love you!
Don't let them forget me!
I said go!
You.
And you.
Ladies, can I have
your attention, please?
You will find food
in your quarters.
Eat as much as you want...
and make sure you get
a good night's rest.
You'll want
to look your best tomorrow.
Oh, and feel free to linger
as long as you want
in the sonic showers.
Cardassians value cleanliness.
Meru, listen to me.
I know things look bad
but don't give up just yet.
We'll find a way
to get out of here.
How?
There must be a resistance cell
operating here on the station.
We'll contact them.
They'll help us get away.
I don't believe this.
Fresh moba.
Do you know how long it's been
since I've seen fresh moba?
Nice.
Nice?
Look at this.
Katterpod beans and...
hasperat...
veklava...
a pot of deka tea.
We could live on this
for a year.
Easy. Easy.
You don't want
to make yourself sick.
Sick?
From too much food?
That would be a change.
If only Taban and the children
were here.
The Cardassians said they
would take care of them
so maybe they will.
Don't count on it.
We need to find a way
to get off this station.
Once we do,
we'll figure out a way
to free your family.
Then what?
We'll hide in the hills.
We'll join the resistance.
I suppose that's possible.
Of course, it is.
Till then, we'll just
need to bide our...
I'm sorry.
I failed to show
a Cardassian soldier
the proper respect.
We all have scars
of one kind or another.
Maybe...
but most aren't
quite so evident.
It's not so bad.
Why do you keep doing that?
What?
Helping me.
First, at the refugee
center and now here.
I don't have many friends.
Well...
you have one now.
Well done.
I can hardly believe
you're the same women
I met yesterday.
In fact, you're not.
Your old lives have ended.
Your pasts have been erased.
You have one purpose
and one purpose only...
to provide comfort and care
to the Cardassian officers
stationed here.
Do that well,
and you'll want for nothing.
Fail and you and your family
will be sent to a labor camp.
Now, remember, ladies...
you're all easily replaceable.
Make one mistake
and I won't hesitate to...
Basso!
That's enough.
Welcome...
to Terok Nor.
I hope your stay here
will be a pleasant one.
I assure you, I will do
everything possible
to make it so.
I suspect that many of you
must be feeling a bit...
uneasy right now.
I'm well aware that among
the Bajoran population
there is a perception
that all Cardassians
are to be feared,
that we are a cruel
and heartless people.
I hope to change that...
not with words,
but with actions...
in the hope that you will come
to appreciate
the better part of our nature.
I assure you...
we are capable
of great kindness.
What of our families?
Are they all right?
Who said you could speak?!
Guards!
Stay where you are.
Your families...
will be well taken care of.
That, I promise you.
What is this?
I...
Basso...
Forgive me, Prefect.
I... didn't notice
the imperfection.
I'll have her removed at once.
Get me a dermal regenerator.
- But...
- Now.
I'm afraid to ask
how you came by such a mark.
It's nothing.
On the contrary.
It's an unfortunate reminder
of the gulf
that exists
between our two peoples.
It must be removed...
immediately.
Just relax.
It's all right.
Relax.
There.
Beautiful.
Carry on.
Well, I'd say congratulations
are in order.
You've all passed
your first test.
Sit down and drink with me.
Mind telling me
what you're smiling about?
The Prophets.
I never realized they had
such a sense of humor.
When I was a child
I dreamed of having
enough food to eat
and pretty clothes to wear,
and now look at me.
I have everything I ever wanted,
and I feel horrible.
That is pretty funny
in a horrible way.
I suppose
if I can survive starvation
I can survive this.
After all, we Bajorans
can survive anything.
You.
Think you can stand there
hiding in a corner all night?
I don't remember seeing you
before.
I just arrived yesterday.
And I bet I know
what you're thinking.
You'd like nothing better
than to get us all drunk
so you could kill
us in our sleep.
Are you sure
you're not part Betazoid?
Come.
Sit on my lap...
and tell me how much you hate
Cardassians.
You Bajoran women,
you're all so bony.
That's because you Cardassians
eat all our food.
You know, I could
have you executed
for that kind of insolence.
And that's one of the reasons
we hate you so much.
Clever girl.
Now, pour me
some more of that kanar
and let's see if we can't
work out our differences.
Let her go.
I said let her go.
All I said to her was...
I don't care
what you were saying.
I don't like
what you were doing.
Now, get away from her.
Are you all right?
Basso...
escort this woman
back to her quarters,
and see that her privacy
is respected.
She will not be disturbed.
I only hope
you won't condemn us all
for the boorish behavior
of one man.
I only hope
you won't condemn us all
for the boorish behavior
of one man.
How did you know
he was going to say that?
Let's just say this is not
the first performance I've seen
of this little... melodrama.
That woman should consider
herself fortunate.
She's caught the Prefect's eye.
As of now, she's off limits
to the rest of us.
As for you...
I know.
I know... more kanar.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Now, one foot
in front of another.
Don't tell me what to do.
I'll put my feet
wherever I want.
I'm a Cardassian.
Whatever you say.
Just try not to stumble
out of any airlocks
on your way home.
I'm not going home;
I'm coming in with you.
No, you're not.
You're going
back to your quarters
and you're going to sleep.
I want comfort,
and I want it now.
You are a comfort woman,
aren't you?
You're dressed like one.
Oh, don't let appearances
fool you.
Mm. That mouth of yours
is going to get you
in trouble someday.
Now, let's go get some... sleep.
I have a better idea.
You go sleep in your quarters.
I'll sleep in mine,
and tomorrow...
Tomorrow, you'll be all mine
to do with as I please.
Oh, I can hardly wait.
Meru, I'm back.
I'm going to have
to shower for a week
to get the smell
of that Legate off of me.
I'll be sure to tell him
you said that.
What are you doing here?
Where's Meru?
Looks like you're going
to have these quarters
all to yourself, at least
for a little while.
I said where's Meru?
She's moving up in the world.
Your friend must have hidden
talents I wasn't aware of.
Our beloved Prefect
has invited her
to share his quarters.
I want to see her.
Do you?
I said take me to her!
Hey!
So, tell me, how's work going
on the ore processing center?
You ought to join
the work detail sometime...
find out for yourself.
All in good time.
Once the center's up and running
we'll all be slaving
away down there.
I have news for you.
About my friend?
I know why you haven't
heard from her
in the last few weeks.
She hasn't been on the station.
What are you talking about?
Word has it she's been off
on a little vacation
with Gul Dukat.
They just got back today.
Why is that woman
so important to you?
She's nothing
but a collaborator.
She is not a collaborator.
She's a comfort woman
for the spoonheads, isn't she?
Mm-hmm. So was I.
For a day.
But I've been watching you.
You have no love
for the spoonheads.
Neither does my friend.
Look, I told you already.
I don't want to join
your resistance cell.
Just leave me alone.
I will.
I promise.
But first, I need for you
to draw a map for me.
A map of what?
The Cardy side of the station.
Well, like you said,
I was only there one day.
Well, anything
you remember will help...
quarters, corridors,
meeting rooms.
Why? What are you planning?
It doesn't concern you.
Now, are you going
to help us or not?
You.
Follow me.
You may enter.
Luma.
Oh! Are you all right?
I've been worried about you
since the night they took you.
I know.
I wanted to get
a message to you.
Has he hurt you?
Who?
Dukat.
Hurt me?
No.
He hasn't hurt me.
I, I wish I knew
how to explain to you
these past few weeks...
make you understand.
Understand what?
That I'm not
the monster you think I am.
You see?
I told you
I'd find a big enough vase.
What do you think?
They're beautiful.
I don't think your friend
approves of the flowers.
Or of me.
Meru...
are you sure this is the woman
you want as your companion?
Yes.
As you wish.
The fact is...
I've treated Meru
with nothing but kindness
and consideration.
If you don't believe me
ask her.
I'll be back
as soon as this meeting
is finished.
It's true.
He's very different
from what I expected.
Don't let that smile
fool you.
He's still the enemy.
It's not that simple.
Yes.
It is.
Meru... listen to me.
While you're in here
playing parlor games
he's busy carrying out
the extermination of our people.
That's not true.
He's written to Central Command
urging them to rethink
their policy towards Bajor.
I don't care
if he played you
a holo-recording
of him on his hand and knees
begging Central Command
to end the occupation.
It would still be a lie!
Like that first night
when he saved you
from that Gul...
that wasn't real.
He set the whole thing up
to win you over.
He told me.
He tells me everything.
You just don't know him.
I don't need to know him.
I know the things he's done.
Look what he did to you.
He took you away
from your family...
from your children.
He's promised to help them.
He's going to send them food
and medical supplies.
That still
doesn't make it right.
What about your husband?
Taban loves you.
How can you forget him
so quickly?
I have not forgotten him.
What do you expect me to do?
Kick and bite Dukat every
time he comes near me?
How is that going to help
Taban or the children?
Oh, is that what you
tell yourself...
that you're doing it
for the children,
the clothes, the food,
the easy living...
that you're doing
it all for them?
Are you that deluded?
It's not for them.
It's for you.
You like it here.
You enjoy playing house
with that murderer.
Don't you see what you are?
What you've allowed
yourself to become?
You're a collaborator.
A collaborator?
Because I share Dukat's bed?
No, because you like
sharing his bed...
because you've fallen
in love with him!
Where are you going?
Back where I belong.
It's composed of ultritium resin
which means it's doubtful
that the Cardassian
sensors will pick it up.
Of course,
there's always a chance.
You let me worry about that.
You sound like you've
done this before.
You'd be surprised.
Remember...
the bomb is set to go off
three minutes
after it's activated.
And once it's activated,
it cannot be disarmed.
So make sure you have
enough time to get away.
How large of a blast radius
are we talking about?
20 meters.
I suggest you plant it
somewhere in Dukat's quarters.
I'll pick the right spot for it.
What about
that Bajoran mistress of his?
What about her?
You cannot risk telling her
what you're doing...
not even to save her life.
Why would I do that?
Like you said,
she's a collaborator.
She deserves whatever she gets.
I'm beginning to find
you very tiresome.
Yeah, I don't like
you much either.
Now, I need you
to take me to Kira Meru.
I have better things to do
than to shuttle you
around this station.
It's time you decided which side
of this gate you want to be on.
I have.
Now, take me to Kira
so that I can apologize to her.
Guard.
A wise decision.
I didn't expect
to see you again.
I came because I owe you
an apology.
The things I said,
they were unfair.
I'd like us to be friends again.
So would I.
Whatever makes you happy,
my dear.
Can I get you something?
Maybe later.
All right.
First thing we do is get you
some new quarters
something close by.
Sounds good.
I have a copy
of that transmission
you requested.
Ah, thank you, Basso.
That'll be all.
What about her?
Don't concern yourself
with Luma.
She's not going to cause us
any more trouble, are you?
That's not what I'm here for.
No, it isn't.
Well, Basso, you heard...
find her some new quarters.
Right away.
This is for you.
I think you'll find it
very interesting.
I'll be in my study
if you need me.
I'll see to my quarters.
Okay, Luma.
Meru, I hope the Cardassians
aren't lying to me
and that they really
will send this message to you.
I know it's only
been a few weeks
that we've been back home,
but you should see the children.
It's like they've been
transformed.
Reon and Pohl are laughing
and playing together.
They've never been happier.
And I swear, little Nerys
must have gained five pounds.
Of course,
they keep asking for you.
I've told them that you're
still at the refugee center.
I think that's best,
at least for the time being.
I can't believe
how much I miss you.
I think about you all the time.
You've saved all our lives.
I hope you realize that.
Never forget it,
not even for an instant.
Every day,
I pray to the Prophets
that you'll find some peace
in this new life of yours.
I believe that even
in the worst of times
we can still find moments
of joy and kindness.
If you can find
that kindness, hold on to it.
And remember, no matter
what happens...
I love you, Meru.
I'll always love you.
Come on, we've got
to get out of here.
Why?
Dukat, get out here, now!
Go!
What?
There's a bomb.
Meru!
Get out of the way!
Meru...
Meru.
I've always hated collaborators.
I mean, what could be worse
than betraying your own people?
During the occupation,
if I ever had any doubt
about what their fate should be
I would think of my mother...
how she gave her life for Bajor.
She was a hero.
They were traitors.
It was that simple.
Or so I thought.
She did what she had to do
to save her family...
to save you.
It doesn't make it right.
Maybe not
but it was her decision to make.
I did some checking.
She died
in a Cardassian hospital
seven years after she
met Dukat... seven years.
Do you know how many Bajorans
died in the labor camps
during that time...
died... while my mother sat
sipping kanar with Dukat?
Tell me something, Nerys.
If you hate her that much,
why did you save her life?
Believe me...
there's a part of me
that wishes that I hadn't.
But the fact is...
no matter what she did...
she was still my mother.