Captain's Personal Log,
Stardate 517...
3, uh...
517...
4?
Computer, what day is it?
Stardate 51721.3.
It's only been two weeks.
I need to talk about this.
I have to justify what's
happened, what I've done...
at least to myself.
I can't talk to anyone else...
not even to Dax.
Maybe if I
just lay it all out in my log,
it'll finally make sense.
I can see
where it all went wrong...
where I went wrong.
I suppose
it started two weeks ago
while I was posting the weekly
casualty list in the Wardroom.
Every Friday morning
for the past three months
I've posted the official list
of Starfleet personnel killed,
wounded or missing in the war.
It's become something
of a grim ritual around here.
Not a week goes by
that someone doesn't find
the name of a loved one
a friend or an acquaintance
on that damned list.
I've grown to hate Fridays.
Who is it, Dax?
Leslie Wong.
The Skipper of the Cairo?
She was an instructor
at the Academy
when I was a sophomore.
Do you know what happened
to the Cairo?
No, just that she
disappeared on patrol
in the Romulan Neutral Zone.
I'll look into it.
Don't bother... I'm sure
it's the same old story.
The Jem'Hadar crossed
the Romulan border
and caught them by surprise.
It's only about the hundredth
time it's happened.
I can't believe
the Romulans allow them
to violate their territory
so brazenly.
Why do they get away with it?
The Romulans have a treaty
of nonaggression and friendship
with the Dominion.
So they're willing to turn
a blind eye to almost anything
in the name of friendship.
What we need to do is
bring the Romulans
into the war on our side.
With the combined forces
of the Federation,
the Klingons and the Romulans
we could finally
go on the offensive.
That's the last thing
the Romulans want.
Think about it.
They're in
the perfect position.
They get to sit back and watch
as their biggest rivals
slug it out
in a long, bloody war.
No one's threatening
their interests.
Why should
they risk their necks?
There's simply
no reason for them
to get involved in our war...
no reason at all.
That was the moment
I made the decision.
It was like I had stepped
through a door
and locked it behind me.
I was going to bring
the Romulans into the war.
It's in their own best
interests to join the war.
That's the key.
That's the reason the Romulans
will finally take action
not to do us any favors
but to protect themselves
from the Dominion.
Okay, let's say
I'm the Romulan Proconsul.
From where I'm sitting
the Dominion isn't
a threat to me.
I have a nonaggression pact
with them.
They are my allies.
You're not going
to put your faith
in some piece of paper, are you?
Not at all.
I've been watching them
very closely
since the beginning of the war
and so far, they've kept
their part of the bargain.
They're violating your territory
almost every day.
What kind of an ally is that?
So they're crossing my backyard
to give the Federation
a bloody nose.
I can't say that makes me feel
very sad.
You can't be naive enough
to think
that the Dominion is going
to stop with the Federation.
When they're finished with us,
they're coming after you.
That's speculation.
The Founders see it
as their sacred duty
to bring order to the galaxy...
their order.
Do you think they'll sit idly by
while you keep
your chaotic empire
right next
to their perfect order? No.
If you watch us go under,
then what you're really doing
is signing
your own death warrant.
But before I plunge my people
into a conflict
that will kill millions
of loyal Romulan citizens
I need something more concrete
than the self-serving argument
of a Starfleet officer.
I need proof
of Dominion duplicity.
Not more words...
proof.
Very good, old man.
You would have made
a decent Romulan.
I prefer the spots
to the pointed ears.
Okay, you've convinced me.
They're going to need evidence.
But if there is evidence
of a Dominion plan
to attack Romulus
it's probably buried
deep in the bowels
of their headquarters
on Cardassia Prime.
Not exactly the most accessible
place in the galaxy.
Hmm...
Not for us, maybe, but there is
someone on this station
who specializes
in gaining access
to places
where he is not welcome.
I must say I'm flattered,
Captain.
I had no idea you held such
a lofty opinion of me.
Your faith in my ability
to retrieve
classified information
from my former homeland
is most gratifying.
Mr. Garak, let's dispense
with the usual repartee
and concentrate
on the issue at hand.
Can you do it or not?
No one wants to see the Dominion
destroyed more than I do
but to go to Cardassia Prime
penetrate one of the most
heavily guarded facilities
in the Quadrant,
steal top secret war plans
and then return them
safely to you
is not just another job.
It's more like a suicide mission
and that is well outside
my field of expertise.
I didn't say you had
to go there yourself.
I have to believe
that a man like you
still has a few contacts
at home...
a colleague
from the Obsidian Order...
an old friend...
a reliable informant...
someone who might owe you
a favor.
Perhaps.
Then I'd say it's time
to call in a favor.
It would mean calling in
all my favors, Captain.
To do what you're asking
would use up
every resource I have left
on Cardassia.
And it may be...
a very messy,
very bloody business.
Are you prepared for that?
I posted my 14th casualty
list this morning.
I'm already involved
in a very messy,
very bloody business.
And the only way
I can see to end it
is to bring the Romulans
into the war.
I am prepared to do
whatever it takes
to accomplish that goal,
but I can't do it alone.
I need help.
Now...
are you in or out?
I'm in.
My father used to say
that the road to hell
is paved with good intentions.
I laid the first stone
right there.
I'd committed myself.
I'd pay any price,
go to any lengths
because my cause was righteous.
My... intentions were good.
In the beginning,
that seemed like enough.
If there's one thing
I've learned over the years
it's that bad news
invariably comes
in the middle of the night.
Kira to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead, Major.
We just received a priority one
communication
from Starfleet Command.
The Dominion
has invaded Betazed.
According to initial reports,
the invasion force
must have come from somewhere
in the Calandra Sector.
Did Starfleet Intelligence
know anything about the buildup?
No. They believed
Calandra was too far
from the Dominion supply lines
to be a threat.
There's plenty of blame
to go around.
The Tenth Fleet was supposed
to be protecting Betazed
and its outlying colonies.
But it was caught out of
position on a training exercise.
What's worse, Betazed's
own defense systems
are obsolete and undermanned.
The planet was theirs
in less than ten hours.
With Betazed in the hands
of the Jem'Hadar,
the Dominion is in a position
to threaten Vulcan,
Andor, Tellar, Alpha Centauri.
If we ever needed a new ally,
it's right now.
Mr. Garak.
It's been three days.
Have you made any progress?
Well, I suppose that depends
on how you look at it.
This is how I look at it:
Betazed has just fallen
to the Dominion
and we need to get
this operation underway.
I share your desire
for swift action, Captain.
In fact,
after our last conversation
I made a few discreet inquiries
among my former associates
still living on Cardassia.
As I anticipated
they shared my loathing
for the current government
and were willing to take on
any assignment
aimed at its destruction.
That sounds like progress to me.
Doesn't it?
Unfortunately,
they're all dead now.
What?
Yes.
All killed within one day
of speaking with me.
I suppose that's a testament
to the effectiveness
of Dominion Security.
One should admire
such efficiency.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I hope you're not
giving up that easily.
After all, the stakes
are much higher
than a few dead operatives.
The fate of the entire Quadrant
hangs in the balance...
or at least that's the case
you made to me.
Do you have another plan?
As a matter of fact, I do
but I suspect
you won't like it.
Try me.
If you want to guarantee
that we obtain evidence
of a Dominion plot to attack
the Romulans
I suggest that we manufacture
that evidence ourselves.
Maybe I should have put a stop
to it right there.
Maybe I should have said
"Thank you very much
for your input, Mr. Garak.
I will take your suggestion
under advisement"
and gone back to my office
and forgotten the whole thing
but I didn't...
because in my heart, I knew
what he was saying made sense.
His name is Vreenak.
He's been a key member
of the Romulan Senate
for the past 14 years.
He's Secretary
of the War Plans Council
Vice Chairman of the Tal Shiar
and one of the most trusted
advisors to Proconsul Neral.
He's also the man
that negotiated
the nonaggression pact
with the Dominion.
Since you're familiar with him
I'll skip the rest
of his biography.
What's important is that he
continues to be one of the most
ardently pro-Dominion voices
in the Senate.
If we can convince him
that the Dominion is a threat
the rest of the Senate
will follow.
All right. How?
Ten days from now
Senator Vreenak will be
making a trip to Soukara
for a diplomatic
meeting with Weyoun.
I am certain
that he can be persuaded
to make a secret detour to DS9
if he were invited
by one Captain Benjamin Sisko.
How do you know
he'll be visiting Soukara?
There are some things
I'd rather not discuss.
May I continue?
Please.
When Senator Vreenak arrives,
you will show him
a holographic recording
of a secret meeting
held at the highest
level of the Dominion
in which the planned
invasion of Romulus
is being discussed.
You will tell the Senator
that this information
was obtained
through various covert means
at great cost
to the Federation.
At least ten good
men lost their lives
bringing it across the line...
that sort of thing.
He will immediately
suspect it's a forgery
but you will assure him
that such a thing
would be impossible.
"You see, Senator
"this is an official Cardassian
transcript.
"It was recorded on a one-time
optolythic data rod
"used for official
record keeping.
"These rods are manufactured
only as needed
"on Cardassia Prime.
"Information can only be
transcribed on them once
and then cannot be altered."
He'll want to examine it.
Of course.
And he will discover,
to his amazement
that it is completely genuine,
at least, so it will appear.
But in reality?
You will have handed him
a genuine optolythic data rod
but it will contain one
of the most perfect forgeries
ever fashioned.
I'm still working
on obtaining the data rod
but I have found the man who
will create the holo-recording.
You realize I can't authorize
a thing like this on my own.
I have to clear it
with Starfleet Command.
Of course, but I suspect
that with the fall of Betazed
they'll be ready to do
whatever it takes
to bring the Romulans
into the war.
I'll let you know.
Uh, one last thing, Captain.
The man we need to forge
this holo-program
is currently sitting
in a Klingon prison
awaiting execution.
To save time
and, incidentally, his life
I thought that perhaps
you could contact
Chancellor Gowron today
and arrange a pardon?
What's his name?
Grathon Tolar.
I cannot tell you
how grateful I am, Captain.
The Klingons were going
to execute me tomorrow.
Of course, they say
that every day.
It's one of the little
games they like to play.
You do understand the terms
of your parole.
Oh, yes.
I have to promise to stay
away from the Klingon Empire.
That'll be tough.
And I have to create
some kind of a special
holo-program for you.
Well, I can hardly wait.
I've never worked
for Starfleet before.
Let's be very clear about this.
You're not working
for Starfleet.
This entire matter
is off the record.
As far as you're concerned,
you're working for me.
Oh, a personal matter.
Something special,
for your eyes only?
Something with, perhaps
five or six Orion slave girls
and... oh...
Mr. Tolar.
I suggest you go
and wait in your quarters.
Mr. Garak will provide you
with all
the information you need.
Garak... is here?
That's right.
Oh... oh...
Well... that's different.
I'll wait in my quarters.
Why I didn't listen
to the voice
in the back of my mind
telling me not to believe
a word he said
I'll never know.
But it didn't take long
for me to come face-to-face
with the fact
that I'd made a mistake.
Odo to the Captain.
Go ahead, Constable.
I'm sorry to disturb you
but do you know a man
named Grathon Tolar?
Yes. Why do you ask?
Because he just tried
to kill Quark.
Sit still, Quark.
You'll be fine.
All right, keep an eye on him.
What happened?
As I understand it, Mr. Tolar
over there came in
about two hours ago
ordered a bottle
of Whelan bitters.
15 minutes later,
he ordered a second bottle
and then a third.
Halfway through
his fourth bottle
he decided to dance
with M'Pella.
She was otherwise
engaged, running
the dabo wheel,
declined his invitation.
He decided to force the issue.
A brief struggle ensued,
and Quark
in an uncharacteristic
display of chivalry
attempted to intervene,
so Tolar stabbed him.
Normally, he'd be
sitting in a holding
cell, but he claims
he's a friend of yours.
He's no friend of mine...
but he is working for me.
It's an extremely
sensitive matter
concerning Federation security.
I can't have any record
of him being on the station.
I see.
I am certainly aware
of the need
for special security measures
during wartime
but, as a matter of law
if Quark chooses
to press charges against Tolar
I have no choice
but to make an arrest.
May I speak to Quark?
How is he?
How do I look?
I'm a man who just
had a brush with death.
He'll be fine.
His ribs deflected the knife
from his major organs.
Bleeding was superficial.
Superficial?
Do you know how much
this shirt cost?
Will you excuse us
for a moment, Doctor?
I'll check on you tomorrow.
Do you intend to press charges?
You bet I do.
What will it take, um...
to, uh, convince you otherwise?
Are you offering me...
a bribe?
I knew it.
Captain, I've always liked you.
I suspected that somewhere deep
down in your heart of hearts
there was a tiny bit of Ferengi
just waiting to get out.
What's your price?
Well... let's start
with replacing my clothes
and M'Pella's clothes.
All right.
I'm not finished.
I think I should be compensated
for the loss of business
I suffered today
which I calculate
as no less than...
five bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
Done.
I'm also having a problem
with Station Security.
They're holding
some cargo containers
which I've been waiting for
because of some missing
import license or something.
I'll handle it.
A-anything else?
No.
I think we can call it a bribe.
And thank you, Captain.
Thank you for restoring my faith
in the 98th Rule of Acquisition.
"Every man has his price."
That was my first moment
of real doubt...
when I started to wonder...
if this whole thing
was a mistake.
So then I went back
to my office...
and there...
was a new casualty list
waiting for me.
People are dying
out there every day!
Entire worlds are struggling
for their freedom
and here I am, still worrying
about the finer points
of morality.
No, I... I had to keep my eye
on the ball.
Winning the war,
stopping the bloodshed...
those were the priorities!
So I pushed on
and every time another doubt
appeared before me
I just found another way
to shove it aside.
Mind if I join you?
Be my guest.
Ops.
Hold. The less I'm seen
parading through Ops,
the better.
I couldn't agree more.
You seem angry.
Who's watching Tolar?
I've locked him in his quarters.
I've also left him
with the distinct impression
that if he attempts
to force the door open
it may explode.
I hope that's
just an impression.
It's best not to dwell
on such minutiae.
In any case, we have far more
important matters to discuss.
I've located a gentleman
willing to sell us
a genuine optolythic data rod.
How do you know it's genuine?
I trust the source,
but rest assured
I will confirm
the rod's authenticity
before I make payment,
which brings me to you.
How much does he want?
I'm afraid he's not
interested in latinum.
The gentleman in question
has requested
to be compensated with...
200 liters of biomimetic gel.
What?!
I don't know why, exactly.
One would assume
it has something to do
with genetic experimentation.
Offer him something else.
Believe me, I wouldn't
be relaying this request
if I thought
he'd take something else.
Biomimetic gel is strictly
controlled by the Federation
and not for sale at any price.
Find someone else
who's willing to sell us a rod.
I wasn't exaggerating
when I told you
about the near impossibility
of obtaining a genuine
Cardassian data rod.
It's something
of a minor miracle
that I was able
to locate this one source.
I'm virtually certain
I won't find another.
I'm afraid we either
give him what he wants
or forget the whole enterprise.
Then let's forget about it.
Ops.
Hold.
200 liters is
out of the question.
There's not that much gel
in the entire sector.
I believe that the quantity
is open to negotiation.
Ops.
Captain, biomimetic gel
is an extremely dangerous
compound, as you know.
I can't release it
without at least some idea
of where it's going.
In the wrong hands,
it could be used
to make biogenic weapons,
or for illegal
replication experiments or to
develop organic explosives...
Perhaps I didn't
make myself clear, Doctor.
This is not a request;
it's an order.
You will package
85 liters of biomimetic gel
for interstellar transport,
and deliver them to Cargo Bay 3.
Is that understood?
Yes.
I'd like this order
in writing, please, sir.
I thought you might.
You should know
that I shall note this in my log
and file an official protest
with Starfleet Medical.
That is your right,
but I want the gel
by the end of the day.
Dismissed.
The Founders have decided
to implement stage two
ahead of schedule.
The invasion of Romulus?
It's too soon.
We're engaged in heavy fighting
all along the border
with the Federation.
The Klingons are preparing
to go on the offensive, and...
Fortunately, the Founders
have better vision than you do.
They can see the opportunities
before us
even when you cannot.
Consider...
the Romulans don't expect
an attack from Cardassia.
The bulk of the Romulan fleet
is still deployed
along the Neutral Zone
with the Federation.
The Founders estimate
we could be on Romulus itself
in less than three weeks.
Three weeks?
I heard
the same kind of estimates
before we attacked
the Federation.
Those plans were ruined
by the incompetency
of your predecessor.
Gul Dukat is a great man.
Gul Dukat is a preening egotist
and a fool.
We offered him
unchallenged control
of the Alpha Quadrant, and all
he could think about
was his daughter.
Now, shall we get back
to the business at hand?
That's it.
Freeze program.
That's all the new material.
The rest of the program plays
exactly as you saw before.
What do you think?
It's, uh, better.
They seem more real.
Yes, and all I had to do
was add
a little petty bickering
and mutual loathing.
So, you are happy.
It's... satisfactory.
You may record the program
onto the data rod now.
I received a message.
Senator Vreenak is on the way.
Excellent.
Done.
Who gets it?
Just... put it in the case.
Ah.
Well... it has been a pleasure
doing business
with you gentlemen.
Call me again if you ever...
You're not going anywhere.
What?
What do you mean?
I mean, you're not leaving
until your work is accepted
by our client.
Well, that isn't fair.
You can't keep me here
against my will.
I haven't done anything wrong.
We had an agreement!
I'm making a new agreement.
If that program passes
inspection, you walk free
but if there is even
the slightest flaw
then I will send you back
to that Klingon prison
and tell Gowron to take his
time while he executes you.
All right. It will pass.
You'll see.
It... will... pass.
I sincerely hope so.
Now, why don't you go back
to your quarters?
I'll be along shortly
to say... hello.
Maybe I was under more pressure
than I realized.
Maybe it was really starting
to get to me.
But I was off the hook.
Starfleet Command had given
the plan their blessing
and I thought
that would make things easier.
But I was the one
who had to make it happen.
I was the one who had to look
Senator Vreenak in his eye...
and convince him that a lie...
was the truth.
So while you're entertaining
the Senator in the Wardroom
I'll take the opportunity
to make a quick search
of his ship's database.
For what?
Well, for any intelligence
information
he may have picked up
on the Dominion in Soukara.
What if you get caught?
Oh, I think
that's highly unlikely.
I doubt the Senator
will be traveling
with more than four bodyguards
at the most.
Two will stand watch
outside the Wardroom
and two will stay
in the landing bay.
I assure you, they'll never know
I was even near their ship.
Just make sure
you don't get caught.
Report.
Sections 52 Baker
through 62 Baker
have been secured.
I have posted armed guards
at every entry point
and I have personally scanned
all compartments
for signs
of surveillance equipment.
Very good, Commander.
Maintain current security
measures until further notice.
No one is to enter this area
except Mr. Garak and myself.
Aye, sir.
Always a pleasure
to see you, Mr. Worf.
Ops to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead, Major.
We've just received
the coded subspace signal
you were waiting for.
Should I reply?
No reply, Major.
Sisko out.
I'll take my leave of you now,
Captain.
Oh, and one last thing.
Vreenak believes
he's on the winning side
so until you can prove otherwise
you may have to put up
with a certain...
acerbic attitude.
Uh, Mr. Garak
after having spent
a week with you
I have developed
a very, very thick skin.
Good luck.
Welcome aboard, Senator.
I'm Captain Benjamin Sisko.
So, you're the Commander
of Deep Space 9...
and the Emissary
to the Prophets
decorated combat officer,
widower, father, mentor.
And, oh, yes...
the man who started the war
with the Dominion.
Somehow I thought
you'd be taller.
Sorry to disappoint you.
To be honest
my opinion of Starfleet officers
is so low
you'd have to work very hard
indeed to disappoint me.
If you'll come with me,
I'll show you to your quarters.
I look forward
to seeing your station...
while it's still here, that is.
The way the war's going
with the Federation
it may not be around
much longer.
Mmm.
A fair approximation, but...
somewhat lacking in aroma.
Real kali-fal should forcibly
open one's sinuses
well before the first sip.
We don't have much experience
in replicating
Romulan beverages.
Of course, all of that
would change
if we became allies
instead of cold warriors.
You are persistent, Captain.
I'll grant you that.
But dogged determination
isn't enough
to change the reality
of your situation.
Time is definitely
not on your side.
The Dominion shipyards
are operating
at 100 percent capacity.
Yours are still being rebuilt.
The Dominion is breeding legions
of Jem'Hadar soldiers every day.
You're experiencing
a manpower shortage.
But most important...
the Dominion is resolved
to win the war at any cost.
You and I both know
the Federation has already
put out peace feelers.
Now, in all candor
if you were in my position,
which side would you choose?
I'd pick the side
most likely to leave us in peace
when the dust settles.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe the Dominion will win
in the end.
Then the Founders will control
what we now call Cardassia
the Klingon Empire
and the Federation.
So, instead of facing
three separate opponents
with three separate agendas,
you'll find yourselves facing
the same opponent on every side.
There's a word for that...
surrounded.
It really is a good replica.
The aroma's
starting to grow on me.
For a moment there, I almost
forgot it wasn't the real thing
but only for a moment.
You make
some very good points, Captain
but it's still
all speculation and theory...
nothing that would warrant
abrogating our treaty
and plunging the Empire
into war.
What if I told you
that the Dominion
is planning a sneak attack
on the Romulan Empire
at this very moment?
Mmm...
I'd want proof.
And with the Cardassian
Fourth Order
protecting their flank
the 23rd Jem'Hadar division
will begin its thrust
across the Glintara Sector.
They should begin
the invasion of Romulus
on the following day.
Once we've taken the homeworld
organized resistance
will crumble
when outlying
systems and colonies
begin looking out
for themselves.
Consolidation
of the entire empire
will take three months at most.
What if the Romulan fleet
reacts faster
than you're anticipating?
What if they pull
all of their forces
away from the Federation border
at the first sign of our attack?
I place my faith
in the Founders.
They say the Romulans
are not ready for war
and will not react fast enough
once it begins.
Now, do you wish
to dispute their judgment?
No, of course not.
I serve the Founders.
As do we all.
Meeting adjourned.
I'd like to examine...
that data rod.
So all I could do was wait...
and see how masterful
Tolar's forgery really was.
So I waited.
Tried to catch up
on my paperwork.
But I-I found it very difficult
to focus on...
criminal activity reports, ha?
Cargo manifests.
So I went back to pacing...
and staring out of the window.
I'm not an impatient man.
I'm not one to agonize over
decisions once they're made.
I got that from my father.
He always says...
"Worry and doubt
"are the greatest enemies
of a great chef.
"The soufflé will either rise
or it won't.
"There's not a damn thing
you can do about it
"so you might as well
just sit back and wait
and see what happens."
But this time...
the cost of failure
was so high...
I found it difficult
to take his advice.
If Vreenak discovered that
the data rod was a forgery
if he realized
that we were trying
to trick them into the war,
it could push the Romulans
even farther
into the enemy camp.
They could start
to openly help the Dominion.
If worse came to worst
they could actually join
the war against us.
I had the distinct feeling
that victory or defeat
would be decided
in the next few minutes.
It's a fake!
So, it all blew up in my face.
And all the lies
and compromises...
the inner doubts
and rationalizations...
all for nothing.
Vreenak was furious.
I can't say I blamed him.
I'd have reacted the same way.
After telling me
in no uncertain terms
that he would expose
this "vile deception"
to the entire Alpha Quadrant
he got back in his shuttle
and headed home.
There didn't seem
to be anything more to do.
So, I went back to work.
Two days later, I got the news.
No one for me today.
I had one.
Maria Tatalia,
wounded in action.
Friend?
Friend of a friend.
Actually, I only met her once.
I don't think she'd remember me.
Friend of a friend
between the two of us.
Well, I know
it sounds a bit strange
but I'd say we're off
to a pretty good start today.
Captain, we just received word
from Starfleet Intelligence
that a Romulan shuttlecraft
carrying a high-ranking Senator
has just been destroyed.
Which Senator?
Senator Vreenak.
He was returning to Romulus
from a diplomatic mission
to Soukara
when his shuttle exploded.
The Tal Shiar are investigating
but preliminary reports
point to sabotage.
They believe that the Dominion
is responsible.
The Dominion assassinated
a Romulan Senator.
On a diplomatic mission.
That changes everything.
It could even bring the Romulans
into the war.
Excuse me.
Get up!
You killed him!
That's right.
That's what you
planned to do all along,
isn't it?
You knew the data rod
wouldn't hold up to scrutiny.
You just wanted
to get him on the station
so that you could plant a bomb
on his shuttle!
It wasn't quite that simple.
I did have hopes that the rod
would somehow pass inspection
but I suspected that Tolar
may not have been
up to the task.
And what about Tolar?
Did you kill him, too?!
Think of them both
as tragic victims of war.
If you can allow your anger
to subside for a moment
you'll see
that they did not die in vain!
The Romulans will enter the war!
There's no guarantee of that!
Oh, but I think that there is.
You see, when the Tal Shiar
finishes examining
the wreckage
of Vreenak's shuttle
they'll find
the burnt remnants
of a Cardassian
optolythic data rod
which somehow miraculously
survived the explosion.
After painstaking
forensic examination
they'll discover that the rod
contains a recording
of a high-level Dominion meeting
at which the invasion of Romulus
was being planned.
And then they'll discover
that it is a fraud!
Oh, I don't think they will
because any imperfections
in the forgery
will appear to be a result
of the explosion.
So, with a seemingly legitimate
rod in one hand
and a dead Senator
in the other...
I ask you, Captain
what conclusion would you draw?
That Vreenak obtained the rod
on Soukara
and that the Dominion killed him
to prevent him from returning
to Romulus with it.
Precisely.
And the more the Dominion
protests its innocence
the more the Romulans
will believe they're guilty
because it's exactly
what the Romulans
would have done in their place.
That's why you came to me...
isn't it, Captain?
Because you knew
I could do those things
that you weren't capable
of doing.
Well, it worked,
and you'll get what you want...
a war between the Romulans
and the Dominion
and if your conscience
is bothering you
you should soothe it
with the knowledge
that you may have just saved
the entire Alpha Quadrant,
and all it cost
was the life
of one Romulan Senator
one criminal...
and the self-respect
of one Starfleet Officer.
I don't know about you
but I'd call that a bargain.
At 0800 hours, station time...
the Romulan Empire
formally declared war
against the Dominion.
They have already struck
15 bases
along the Cardassian border.
So...
this is a huge victory
for the good guys.
This may even be the turning
point of the entire war.
There is even
a "welcome to the fight" party
tonight in the Wardroom.
So...
I lied.
I cheated.
I bribed men to cover the crimes
of other men.
I am an accessory to murder.
But the most damning thing
of all...
I think I can live with it.
And if I had to do it
all over again...
I would.
Garak was right about one thing.
A guilty conscience
is a small price
to pay for the safety
of the Alpha Quadrant
so I will learn...
to live with it.
Because I can live with it.
I can live with it.
Computer...
erase that entire personal log.