The Dominion has solidified its hold
in the Kalandra Sector.
They're trying to establish a supply line
running through Betazoid space
into the Argolis Cluster.
If they succeed, they will be able
to launch an attack against Vulcan.
Starfleet's going to try to cut them off
near the Tibor Nebula.
The Seventh Fleet
will be engaging the enemy in the morning.
DAX: The Seventh Fleet
is still at half-strength.
They took heavy losses at Sybaron.
Well, let's just hope
they can get the job done.
On a happier note,
I do have a bit of good news.
That makes a welcome change.
The Romulans have forced the Dominion
to retreat from the Benzite system.
That is good news.
The question is,
will the Romulans be willing
to leave Benzar after the war is over?
Once they capture territory,
they very rarely give it up.
Right now we need to concentrate
on beating the Dominion.
We'll worry about the Romulans later.
As some of you already know
Major Kira, Jake, and I
will be leaving for Bajor at 2200.
There's a war on.
This isn't a time for a vacation.
The archaeologists excavating B'Hala
have found something
they want the Emissary to see.
We'll be returning tomorrow night.
That's all, people.
"Will the Romulans leave Benzar?"
You love to bring up
the worst-case scenario
in these meetings, don't you?
Somebody has to.
Besides, everyone expects me
to be dour and suspicious.
I don't want to disappoint them.
If only they knew the real you.
That is the real me...
at least as far
as everyone else is concerned.
I can't tell you how pleased we are
by your visit, Emissary.
I'm glad to be here, Ranjen.
Oh, there's no need
to keep calling me Ranjen.
I'm a simple monk.
My order is quite informal.
You've certainly been busy.
The last time I visited the ruins,
none of these tunnels had been cut yet.
It's been a great deal of work
but we do it gladly.
Excavating the Holy City is a privilege.
Our efforts are an expression
of our faith in the Prophets
and in the Emissary.
SISKO: It's very inspiring to see.
-Something wrong, Jake?
-( sighs ) No.
It's just that my dad seems
to be taking his role as Emissary
very seriously these days.
You say that like you think
it's a bad thing.
Well, you have to admit, I mean...
it's a long way to come
to see some old ruins.
They may have found
some very important religious artifacts
in these "old ruins."
Yeah, I hope so.
Otherwise, I don't have a story.
Hey, try to look
like you're enjoying yourself.
Your father needs this.
It's good for him not to have to think
about the Dominion for a few hours.
( bats squeaking )
Oh, don't let the bats bother you.
-( bats chittering )
-KIRA: Don't worry. They rarely bite.
JAKE: Rarely? Uh, ugh.
We're directly below the Temple of B'Hala.
These walls predate the ancient city
by 10,000 years.
Uh, who built this place?
We don't know much about
the original inhabitants
but it appears they abandoned this site
some 25,000 years ago.
Over time, sediment buried the ruins.
And then B'Hala was built on top of them.
Precisely.
In here.
It's over 30,000 years old.
These inscriptions...
they look like ancient Bajoran
but I can't quite make it out.
RANJEN: Neither can we.
Though we've been able to piece together
a few of the translations.
The syntax is unusual
but all forms of Bajoran
share certain root-ideograms.
You may recognize this one.
"Welcome."
Here's where it gets interesting.
I see you recognize it.
Wha-what? I don't.
It says...
"Welcome, Emissary."
Now you know why I asked you here.
The Sisko has come.
The circle is complete.
The Reckoning must begin.
The Reckoning?
Much will depend on the Sisko.
He is corporeal.
Limited.
He is the Sisko.
He will not waver.
He is of Bajor.
He will bring the Reckoning.
What is it you expect of me?
It will be the end.
Or the beginning.
I don't understand.
The Sisko will know.
( grunts )
Dad?
Are you okay?
( sighs )
Yeah.
The Prophets...
they were here.
They spoke to me.
You had a vision, Emissary.
We saw nothing.
What did they say?
They mentioned something
about a Reckoning.
Is that a part of some prophecy?
Not one that I know of.
Let's get out of here.
It's all right, Jake.
We'll be leaving soon.
I have got to find out
what those inscriptions say.
I wish we could translate them
more quickly
but we don't have the resources.
Fortunately, we do.
I had a pretty good idea what this was
the minute I laid eyes on it.
That confirms it.
It's a slab of stone
with some writing on it.
Dax...
What do you want me to say, Benjamin?
I'm not picking up any
residual energy readings--
certainly nothing that would explain
how it threw you across the room.
I want you to translate the inscriptions.
I was afraid you were going to say that.
The Ranjen's translation program.
It's not complete,
but at least it's a start.
Good luck.
( sighs )
( chimes jingling )
CLERGYMAN: Services are about to begin.
Captain, services are about to begin.
WORF: Ops to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
WORF: We just received
a communication from Bajor.
Kai Winn is on her way to the station.
Welcome to Deep Space Nine, Your Eminence.
Thank you, Emissary.
What brings you to the station?
I should think that would be clear.
You removed an artifact
from an archaeological site
without consulting the Vedek Assembly.
I meant no disrespect.
You can understand
how we would be sensitive to such matters.
During the Occupation,
the Cardassians plundered
Bajor's historical treasures
as if it were their right.
I never imagined that you would behave
in such a manner.
I assure you that the artifact
will be returned
as soon as I've finished studying it.
I was not aware that you had
expertise in Bajoran history.
-I don't.
-Then why not leave the artifact
in the hands of those who do?
There are scholars on Bajor
who've devoted their lives
to the study of such things.
I understand, but I brought it here
because I believe
that's what the Prophets want.
I see.
Then I take it this has something to do
with your vision?
Exactly.
Forgive me.
I-I didn't realize
that the Prophets told you
to bring the relic here.
Well, they didn't... not in so many words.
I see.
Then exactly what did they say?
( sighs )
It's difficult to explain.
The Prophets are not always clear.
Well, since they have never spoken to me
I'll have to take your word for it.
All I know is, for now, it belongs here.
Who am I to argue
with the Emissary of the Prophets?
And then she contacted Starfleet
and lodged a formal protest.
Is that why Admiral Ross
wanted to talk to you?
Well, how'd it go?
He told me to stop meddling
in Bajoran affairs
and return the damn tablet.
You know how Starfleet feels
about this Emissary thing.
It makes them very uncomfortable
that you've allowed the Bajorans
to view you as a religious icon.
It used to make you uncomfortable, too.
Not anymore.
I guess the Prophets have spoken to me
one too many times.
I remember when you used
to call them "wormhole aliens."
Wormhole aliens or Prophets...
it really doesn't matter.
The fact is, they exist out of time
and over the centuries
they've given the Bajorans
glimpses of the future
glimpses that the Bajorans
have written down
to help them guide succeeding generations.
If whatever is written here
can help me avoid mistakes
can help me make the right decisions
then I'd be a fool to ignore it.
Fair enough, but if you don't mind
I'm going to continue to think
of them as wormhole aliens.
All I know is...
that they have a relationship with Bajor
that stretches back over a thousand years.
They care what happens to Bajorans.
They proved that
when they kept the Dominion fleet
from coming through the wormhole.
Didn't you have to talk them into it?
Didn't they say they would exact
some kind of penance for helping you?
Yes, but they listened,
and they saved Bajor
and the rest of the Alpha Quadrant.
Now they're asking me
for something in return.
I don't know what it is yet
and I'm not going to return
the tablet until I do.
It's the key. I can feel it.
I hope you're wrong about that, Benjamin.
What have you got?
The computer has translated
part of the inscription.
It probably lacks the eloquence
of the original passage
but you'll get the gist of it.
Here it is in modern Bajoran.
SISKO: "The time of Reckoning is at hand.
"The Prophets will weep.
"Their sorrow will consume...
the Gateway to the Temple."
Tell me I'm wrong...
but isn't the Gateway
to the Temple Deep Space Nine?
I was just telling you
what the translation said.
I did not say I believed it.
Well, I'm not worried.
If you look hard enough
you'll find a Bajoran prophecy
for just about anything.
The ancient texts are a tangle
of vague contradictions.
Well, this one is anything but vague
and Bajoran prophecies
have an odd way of coming true.
Don't say you believe in this stuff, too?
Odo believes in preparing for the worst.
True.
He's as bad as the Bajorans.
Business hasn't been this slow
since the Dominion was here.
You know, I feel I have a civic duty
to do something
about all this doom and gloom
which is why I want to tell you
that I've extended happy hour.
Extended it?
From now on, every hour is happy hour...
at least until business picks up.
Eat, drink, and be merry.
For tomorrow, we die.
So what does the Captain say about this?
He is reserving judgment
until the computer
has finished the translation.
Who knows? The rest
of the tablet probably says
"Go to Quark's. It's happy hour."
I like the way you think, Doctor.
Well, this is ridiculous.
Nothing's going to happen.
Someday, we're all going
to look back on this and laugh.
( deep rumbling )
ODO: What was that?
How did that prophecy go again?
KIRA: You don't have to do this, you know.
ODO: Don't have to do what?
Sit here, watch me eat.
I don't mind.
In fact, I rather enjoy it.
You eat with such gusto...
most of the time.
Not today.
I just wish that we knew more
about the Reckoning.
It would give us a better idea
of what the Prophets want from us.
It seems to me that, if the Prophets
want the Bajoran people
to follow a given path
they should provide
more specific directions.
It doesn't work like that.
Maybe it should.
The Kai would say that you lack faith.
And you would agree.
I just don't know how people
make it through the day without it.
We manage.
Besides, I do have faith in some things.
( chuckling ) Such as?
You.
I'll try not to disappoint you.
No doubt you've heard
the latest news from Bajor.
About the flooding
in the Rakantha Province, yes.
There was also an earthquake
in the Kendra Valley last night.
This morning, a tornado struck Tamulna.
Our sensors indicate
that Bajor has been affected
by the instability of the wormhole.
How comforting.
Tell me, do your sensors
have an explanation
for the instability itself?
No.
Then I'll give you one.
You've angered the Prophets
by taking the tablet from Bajor.
As the spiritual leader
of the Bajoran people
I'm asking you to return it.
And as the Emissary of the Prophets
I will ask you to give me
more time to study it.
I believe it is the will of the Prophets.
Well, I disagree.
This is a formal request
from the First Minister
for you to turn over the relic to me.
You must have been very persuasive.
This is the first time
you and Shakaar have agreed on anything.
If you deny his request, I promise you
it will damage relations
between Bajor and the Federation.
The tablet...
will be on its way to Bajor
on the morning transport.
( places padd on desk )
As will I.
You're sending it back?
And I was just starting to have fun.
I'm not letting you off the hook, old man.
I need these inscriptions translated.
I can work off the holo-recordings
I took yesterday.
Have you made any more progress?
Good news or bad?
-That depends.
-On what?
On what this ideogram means.
The computer has given me
two possibilities.
They are?
During the Reckoning
the Bajorans will either "suffer horribly"
or "eat fruit."
"Eat fruit"?
Given the tone
of the rest of the inscriptions
I would bet on horrible suffering.
What else do you have?
You'll love this. It's about you.
"Once the Reckoning begins,
the Emissary will..."
Go on.
I was hoping you could tell me.
Well, the rest of the
inscription's damaged.
Oh, that figures.
( deep rumbling )
Oh, I wish the wormhole
would stop doing that.
So do I. Keep at it, old man.
Just do me one favor.
If you talk to the Prophets again
ask for a dictionary...
please.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
Captain, I have a message for you
from General Martok.
Go ahead.
He's dispatched
three Klingon attack cruisers
to bolster the defense perimeter
around the Dorala system.
Good. I just hope they can hold out
until Starfleet sends in reinforcements.
The Klingons will hold out.
Martok will see to it.
Long day?
They seem to get longer.
You'll feel better in the morning...
once the Kai is off the station.
( chuckling )
She may be the spiritual leader
of millions of Bajorans
but she is not an easy woman to like.
Well, if it's any comfort
I don't think she likes you, either.
I've known that for a while.
I guess I should have consulted her
before I brought the artifact
up to the station.
She would have tried to stop you.
Ah... that's why I didn't ask her.
In a way, I feel sorry for her.
She spends her whole life
in service to the Prophets.
Then one day, after years
of self-sacrifice and commitment
she gets her reward. She's elected Kai.
Should've been the greatest
moment of her life.
But my being the Emissary
spoiled it for her.
Well, the Kai's always been
the spiritual leader of Bajor
but Winn has to share that role with you
and to make matters worse
you're an outsider, a non-Bajoran.
That's something
she can never forgive you for.
I guess that's why she made
such an issue of the whole thing.
Well, she's jealous of you
and of your relationship
with the Prophets.
I'm a little envious myself.
Why?
You speak with the Prophets.
They listen to you.
That's...
that's a rare gift.
Certainly nothing I asked for.
I guess that's why I don't
resent you, but the Kai does.
I'll keep that in mind.
Is something wrong, Eminence?
What makes you say that, child?
You seem troubled.
Not at all.
I am quite relieved
the Emissary has decided
to do the right thing.
Well, you didn't leave him
much choice, did you?
I suppose you think
I enjoyed forcing his hand.
I assure you, I did not.
I wish the situation had been resolved
more amicably.
Perhaps the next time
we have a disagreement
he'll consider my wishes
more thoughtfully.
The next time?
You're anticipating more disagreements?
I merely meant to express
my hope that, in the future
we can work together
for the good of Bajor.
Of course.
After all, you are on the same side,
aren't you?
Naturally.
We both serve the Prophets.
There is no higher calling.
( deep rumbling )
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Yes?
Jake-o.
You're up late.
Oh, so are you.
What's on your mind?
I don't know. I guess I just wanted to see
if you're all right.
I'm fine.
Since when did you become a worrier?
I don't know.
It's this Emissary stuff.
It scares me a little.
Twice now...
twice in one year...
Dr. Bashir's called me
down to the Infirmary
to tell me something was wrong with you
and there you were
lying unconscious on a bio-bed
having visions or something.
And there...
all I could do was just stand there
and, and wonder...
if you were ever going to wake up.
I know it hasn't been easy, Jake.
I don't want it to happen again.
You know, I didn't ask
to be the Emissary...
but, for better or worse,
I guess that's what I am...
except for being your dad.
Why do you always have to be
so damned mysterious?
Answer me.
I am tired of your riddles!
If there's something
you need me to do, say so!
( yelling )
Let me guess.
You accidentally knocked it over.
Not exactly.
I didn't think so.
So what did happen?
I just had this uncontrollable urge
to smash the tablet.
Oh, I get those urges all the time.
Of course, I never act on them.
I'm not reading
any residual energy signatures.
That's impossible.
Check the station's internal sensors.
Nothing.
I tell you, I saw something.
We believe you, Captain.
Oh, please, Constable, don't patronize me.
Sisko to Ops. Report.
We just experienced
a station-wide power drain.
We're attempting to determine the source.
Keep me informed.
WORF: Aye, sir.
It's possible the power drain is related
to this energy discharge you saw.
I'm starting to think the same thing.
Benjamin, you're not getting
another urge, are you?
No.
I've done what I needed to do.
I know this might sound strange
but I think the Prophets
wanted me to shatter the tablet.
Try explaining that to Kai Winn.
I can't believe that you'd be so petty
as to destroy the artifact
rather than turn it over to me.
That's not why I did it.
You expect me to believe
that the Prophets wanted you
to destroy a priceless piece
of Bajor's history?
That's exactly what you have to believe.
And why would they do that?
I wish I had an answer for you.
Well, I'm sure you'll
come up with something.
You and I haven't always
seen things eye to eye
but we have one thing in common--
we both believe that the Prophets
have a plan for Bajor.
Now, sometimes,
it's not easy to see the path
they've laid out for us.
Right now, I don't know
what they want from me
but I'm willing to take a leap of faith
and trust that they're guiding me
and I'm asking you to
take that leap with me.
There's no need
for a leap of faith, Emissary.
The Prophets have made it quite clear.
Two-thirds of the Rakantha wheat harvest
have been destroyed by floods.
Earthquakes have devastated
Kendra Province
leaving hundreds homeless.
Bajorans are suffering because of you.
They're paying the price
for your act of sacrilege.
Odo to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
ODO: You'd better come down
to the Promenade, sir.
Is there a problem?
ODO: I'll let you be the judge of that.
I think we've found the source
of the power fluctuations.
When I tried to talk to her,
she ignored me.
( wind whistling )
( glass exploding )
( voice reverberating) You...
are the Sisko.
Keep your hands off your weapons.
It's a Prophet.
Why have you taken this woman's body?
This vessel is willing.
The Reckoning...
it is time.
SISKO: The Reckoning... what is it?
The end...
or the beginning.
I don't understand.
I await Kosst Amojan.
The Evil One.
A Pah-wraith
banished from the Celestial Temple.
You're saying a Pah-wraith
will take corporeal form as well?
The battle will be joined.
This battle... is it to be fought here?
Bajor will be reborn.
Shabren's Fifth Prophecy--
the Rebirth.
If the Evil One is destroyed
it will bring a thousand years of peace--
the Golden Age of Bajor.
If it is destroyed?
Who will prevail is not known.
What do you want from me?
Am I supposed to help you in some way?
The Sisko has completed his task.
Forgive my blindness.
Prophet, hear me.
I am the Kai of Bajor.
I offer myself to you
as your humble servant.
I await their vessel.
Speak to me.
Tell me what I should do.
We're evacuating.
You can't be serious.
This battle could destroy the station.
Then don't let it be fought here.
I don't have any choice.
Yes, you do.
We can flood the Promenade
with chroniton radiation.
Are you suggesting that we kill a Prophet?
I won't do that.
BASHIR: You don't have to.
If you ramp up the chroniton levels slowly
you'll give the wormhole alien
a chance to leave
Kira's body without getting hurt.
DAX: We have everything rigged
and ready to go.
Just say the word.
No.
Benjamin.
Deep Space Nine is critical
to the defense of the Federation.
We cannot risk destroying it.
When the Dominion fleet
was about to come through the wormhole
I asked the Prophets for their help.
They gave it to me.
Now they're asking for my help.
They need to fight this battle here, now.
I'm not going to jeopardize my crew
but I'm not going to stand
in the way of the Prophets, either.
What if the Prophets lose?
Are you willing to sacrifice Kira?
The Prophet said she was willing
to be their instrument.
And you believe that?
I do.
I know how important
her faith is to her and...
I have no doubt that
she would allow the Prophets
to use her as their instrument.
I'll notify Starfleet that
we're abandoning the station.
Begin the evacuation immediately.
ODO: Hurry along, now. Hurry along.
-Is this transport full?
-There's room.
I'm going to check the
Promenade for stragglers.
Odo, you should've helped us
persuade the Captain to end this.
I had to respect Kira's wishes.
If it were Dax, I am not sure
I could've done the same.
Well, just be grateful
you didn't have to make that choice.
For your sake, I hope
the Prophets are victorious.
They will be
if Kira has anything to do with it.
Come on.
Report.
We expect to be down to a skeleton crew
within the hour.
Very well.
What did Starfleet have to say?
I managed to convince them
that we couldn't afford
to defy the Prophets.
WORF: They are the only thing
that's keeping the Dominion
from coming through the wormhole.
The only problem is, there's no guarantee
the Prophets will win this battle.
Odo to Sisko.
Go ahead, Constable.
ODO: Captain, there's a group of Bajorans
on the Promenade
who are refusing to leave.
WINN: Tera dak embah ihsehelm ran embah...
ALL: de-ram ta-meen.
Tera dak ihsehelm
ran embah...
ALL: de-ram ta-meen...
The last transports are standing by.
WINN: Tera dak ihsehelm ran embah...
Eminence.
...ta-meen.
Emissary.
These people have to go.
We're offering prayers
for the Prophets' victory.
The Prophets will hear your prayers
wherever you are.
It isn't safe here.
Then why are you still here, Emissary?
The Prophet told you your task was done.
I am Captain of this station
and I will do everything
in my power to save it.
Now, are you going to
tell these people to go
or shall I?
My children
the Prophets have heard your prayers.
You must go.
Take them to the transports.
All right, this way.
Congratulations, Emissary.
Thanks to you the Prophets'
victory is at hand.
I hope you're right.
Where is your faith, Emissary?
You don't think the Evil One
will be victorious, do you?
Rest assured, the Golden Age is upon us.
The Prophets and the people
will be as one.
Think of it.
There will be no need for vedeks or kais
or even Emissaries.
Kosst Amojan has chosen its vessel.
Let it begin.
Leave my son and take me instead!
Your Emissary offers himself to us.
His faith wavers.
( grunting )
( groaning )
Emissary, we must go.
Benjamin, Worf is standing by in Ops.
He can trigger the chroniton generator
at your command.
You can still end this, Ben.
No, I've got to play this thing out.
That is your son out there.
Don't you think I know that?
The Prophets will protect him.
They're trying to kill him.
No. They're trying
to destroy the Pah-wraith.
The Prophets will not let
anything happen to him.
How do you know that?
I know.
We've got to get out of here.
According to the sensors,
the energy building between them
could explode at any second.
I'm not going to leave Jake here.
We must go, Emissary.
Benjamin...
Get out of here!
Get off the station, both of you!
That's an order!
Come, child. We must go.
Dax to Worf.
Go ahead.
Meet me at Airlock Eight. We're leaving.
Go on ahead.
Airlock Eight is down to the right.
This way. Move quickly.
Let's go. Come on.
Hurry up.
It's okay, it's okay.
I think the transport is down here.
No!
COMPUTER:
Chroniton levels at 37% and rising.
May the Prophets forgive me.
Jake...
SISKO: Captain's Log, supplemental.
The station's population has returned
and repairs are underway.
Major Kira has recovered
from her experience...
but my son is still in the Infirmary.
Jake?
He'll be, uh, laid up for a few days
but he'll be all right.
May I see him?
Oh, yes.
Jake...
Dad.
How are you feeling?
Could be worse.
You'll be up and about in no time.
I don't know what to say.
Say you're happy to see me.
You know I am.
I wish I...
I want to explain what happened...
but I'm not sure that I can.
You don't have to explain.
When the Pah-wraith was inside me
I could feel its hatred
and I knew that no matter what
it couldn't be allowed to win...
even if it meant I had to die.
You did the right thing.
How was the prayer service?
To tell you the truth
I didn't pay that much attention.
I'm still trying to make sense
out of everything that happened.
I mean, of all the people on this station
the Prophets chose me.
I'm not sure I know why
I deserve that honor.
Perhaps that's why you were chosen.
You have faith and humility.
I heard that you told the Captain
that I was willing to give my life
to serve the Prophets.
I appreciate that you respect my beliefs.
Just the same, I wouldn't have minded
if the Prophets had chosen someone else.
I have to go.
I'll drop by Security
after I take the Kai to her shuttle.
The Emissary couldn't escort me himself?
He's with his son.
I would think he'd want to thank me.
For what?
I prevented the destruction
of this station.
I saved the Emissary's life
and the life of his son.
Don't pretend you did it for the Captain.
I did it for Bajor.
If you haven't heard,
the floodwaters have receded
and the earthquakes have stopped.
And you're going to take credit for that?
I take it as a sign I did the right thing.
You defied the will of the Prophets
and you did it
because you couldn't stand
the fact that a human, an infidel,
had a stronger faith than you.
The Emissary was willing
to sacrifice his own son
to serve the Prophets.
My faith is as pure as the Emissary's.
I think you're confusing faith
with ambition.
I'm not confusing anything,
child, you are.
The Prophets chose you
as their instrument.
That doesn't mean you can speak for them.
Because of your interference,
the Reckoning was stopped.
The evil still exists.
And I'm not sure if even the Prophets know
what that will mean for Bajor.