MALE:
How about it?
FEMALE:
Can I get some
service please?
How long's it take?
I've been
waiting forever.
This isn't what I wanted.
Having a bad day?
Like you care.
Fizz, Froth, Flip
Finial, Foam and Flare.
What's going on
at that table anyway?
I... take it there's a problem
with your drink replicator?
A problem?
No... can't be.
If there were a problem,
I would have submitted
an emergency maintenance request
this morning.
And if I
had done that
Chief O'Brien
would have assured me
that Rom would fix it
right away.
Then, of course,
Rom would have promised me
that Nog would fix it
before the end of the day.
And since this is
the end of the day
and there is no Nog in sight
we can only draw
one conclusion--
that I don't
have a problem.
Is your drink replicator
broken?
You're quick today.
Do you want me
to fix it or not?
You?
That's right.
Nog had a chance to take
a trip to Ferenginar,
and I told him
that I would cover for him
while he was away.
Why?
Because he did a favor
for me last week,
so I owe him.
But...
that's work for a mechanic...
a repairman, a lowly engineer.
I'll tell Chief O'Brien
you said that.
Ugh...
A supernova
and a Silven surprise.
She can't do this.
Why not?
I...
It-it-it's not right.
She's above
that sort of thing.
Those hands weren't
meant for poking around
inside some filthy
drink replicator.
They were meant
for higher pursuits.
You're in love.
That's the most ridiculous thing
you've said this year.
Really?
Really.
It must kill you
that she's married to Worf.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Hmm.
And since you're not going
to order something
would you please
step aside
so that I can do
my job?
Of course.
By the way, that's not
a Silven surprise.
It's a silken sunrise.
Is that it?
That's right.
Hey, can I see it?
No.
Nog.
It's an official
diplomatic message
from the Federation Council
to the Grand Nagus.
It's for his eyes only.
Yeah, but you know
what's in it.
Maybe.
It's a proposal for
an alliance, isn't it?
I mean, the Federation sends
the only Ferengi in Starfleet
to personally deliver
a diplomatic message
to the Grand Nagus?
Something big is up.
You told me you weren't coming
on this trip as a reporter.
I'm not.
I-I came to see Ferenginar.
I've heard a lot about it.
I can't wait to see the-the rain
and-and the muck...
Good.
Because while I'm delivering
the message to the Grand Nagus
you'll have plenty of time
to play tourist.
Shenandoah,
this is Starbase 257.
You've been cleared
to leave our defense perimeter.
Remain at one-half impulse until
you've passed the outer marker.
Acknowledged.
I don't get to see the Nagus?
Now why would you want
to see the Grand Nagus?
My father told me to say hello.
A-a-and...
to... give the Nagus
his best wishes.
You're going to have
to do better than that.
And...
because I told the editor
of the Federation News Service
that I could get
an exclusive interview with Zek.
Jake! You promised me
you weren't coming along
as a reporter.
I didn't promise, okay?
I just sort of... you know?
Okay, I promised,
but this could be
a really big story, Nog.
The people have a right to know.
Forget it. You're not
getting anywhere near
the Grand Nagus.
I have no further comments.
( beeping )
What's that?
I'm not sure.
I'm having trouble
with our long-range scanners.
Looks like... our sensors
are being jammed.
( alarm blares )
Uh-oh.
Hang on.
Where'd they
come from?
I don't know,
but it looks
like they're heading
for the starbase.
We're not sticking
around, are we?
Not in a runabout,
we're not.
We're no match for a wing
of Jem'Hadar fighters.
See if you can open a channel
to Deep Space 9.
Something's wrong.
I think they're jamming
our com system.
But why would they do that?
Because one of them's
turned around
and now he's coming after us.
You do realize you're taking us
deeper and deeper
into Dominion-held space.
We don't have much choice.
Every time I try to change
course, they gain on us.
They're gaining on us anyway.
We might as well try
and head for the Federation.
If we keep going
in this direction,
we'll run into
Cardassia Prime
and that won't be
much fun at all.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
We are within range
of enemy weapons.
( explosion )
Thanks for the warning.
All right, when I go to impulse,
raise the forward shields
and transfer auxiliary power
to the phasers.
We're dropping out of warp?
If we have to fight,
I'd rather do it at impulse.
At least we'd have an edge
in maneuverability.
You're a Ferengi.
Why don't you try
making a deal or something?
It doesn't seem
they're very interested
in talking.
Stand by.
Here they come.
Shields down 30 percent.
I see it.
( explosion )
We're losing main power!
Keep the weapons on line.
Everything else is expendable,
including life support.
( explosion )
There's another ship coming in,
bearing 170 mark 215.
Jem'Hadar or Cardassian?
It's, uh...
it's the Defiant.
What?
That's not the Defiant.
That ship's registry number
is NCC-74...
210.
USS Valiant.
Valiant?
Great name! I hope they tear
that Jem'Hadar ship apart
piece by--
Jake.
Jake!
FEMALE:
Are you all
right, sir?
( groans )
Yeah.
Uh...
it's nothing serious...
Cadet, um...
Chief?
Acting Chief Petty Officer
Dorian Collins.
The Captain's asked me
to escort you both
to the Bridge.
If you'll follow me.
FEMALE:
Main power holding.
Auxiliary power
on standby.
Shields holding
at 84 percent.
Helm, bring us about
to course 215 mark 310.
215 mark 310.
Aye, sir.
Set quantum torpedo warheads
to maximum yield, full spread.
( explosion )
Maximum yield, full
spread. Aye, sir.
( explosion )
Helm, initiate attack
pattern sierra-four.
HELM:
Sierra-four.
Aye, sir.
Shields now at 78 percent.
Transfer auxiliary power
to shields.
This is Red Squad.
Red Squad?
It was a group of elite cadets
at the Academy.
They were...
the best of the best.
Red Squad received
special training
special quarters,
special everything.
They have their own ship?
I've heard of cadets...
getting command of
a runabout or a shuttle
but not a starship.
Fire.
( cheering )
As you were.
This is the Captain.
Stand down
from Red Alert.
All stations submit damage
and casualty report
to the First Officer.
Glad to see you made it
in one piece.
I'm Tim Watters,
Commanding Officer.
Welcome aboard.
Thank you... sir?
"Sir" is correct, Ensign.
I was given
a battlefield commission
and command of this vessel
by the late Captain Ramirez.
Using that authority, I have
commissioned and promoted
other members of Red Squad
as needed.
I see.
Well, I'm Ensign Nog
and this is Jake Sisko.
We're from Deep Space 9.
Sisko.
You're Benjamin Sisko's son.
That's right.
Ah, I've heard a lot
about your father.
I see you're not following
in his footsteps.
No. I'm a reporter.
You should really get
that looked at. Chief?
Sir?
Escort Mr. Sisko
to Sick Bay.
Aye, Captain.
This way, sir.
FEMALE:
Preliminary
damage report, sir.
Oh, thank you.
Ensign Nog, Commander Karen
Farris, our First Officer.
Commander.
Ensign.
Sir, the Engine Room
also reports
that we still have power spikes
cropping up all through
the deuterium injector
start-up routine.
I thought we had that
under control.
FARRIS:
I did, too, sir.
Have you recalibrated
the lateral impulse
control system?
No.
What does that have
to do with the injectors?
Well, the impulse system shares
some of the same power relays
used in the injector
start-up routine.
We'll try it.
Mr. Nog, why don't you wait
in my ready room.
Yes, sir.
The training cruise was
supposed to last three months.
We had seven regular officers
and a crew of 35 cadets.
The plan was for the cadets
to run the ship
while the officers
observed
and critiqued
our performance.
So, uh, this was
a training ship?
Like the other one, the, um...
uh... the Republic.
Not quite.
The Republic's
an old ship.
I don't think
she's left
the Terran system
in 50 years.
The Valiant's a state-
of-the-art warship.
Our mission was
to circumnavigate
the entire Federation
before returning home.
The entire Federation?
With a ship of cadets?
Not just cadets,
Mr. Sisko.
Red Squad cadets.
We were transiting the Kepla
Sector when war broke out.
As you probably know,
a Dominion invasion force
swept through that sector
on the first day.
So you were caught
behind enemy lines.
Correct.
We were trying to make our way
back to Federation-held space
when we encountered a Cardassian
battle cruiser near El Gatark.
That was our first taste
of combat.
In the first 15 minutes
four regular officers
were killed.
Three others were
critically wounded
including
Captain Ramirez.
Is that when
you took command?
No.
When I got to the Bridge,
the Captain was
in pretty bad shape,
but he was lucid
and he refused
to go to Sick Bay.
We had lost main power
and we were adrift
but the Cardassian cruiser
was no better off.
So it was a race
against the clock--
ship that got main power
back on line first
would have a decisive advantage.
The... the Captain, he...
he was amazing.
He directed the entire
damage-control effort
with a punctured lung
and massive internal injuries.
He was a great man.
And he won the race.
We got weapons
and impulse engines
back on line in three hours.
And then we destroyed
that Cardie ship.
The next day,
just before he died
the Captain ordered me
to take command of the Valiant.
( laughs )
It's unbelievable!
You've spent eight months
behind enemy lines.
I didn't do it alone.
The crew deserves
the real credit.
We have cadets here
as young as 17
who are doing the job
of officers twice their age.
But we're also seriously
undermanned.
I could use another officer.
I'd be happy to do
whatever I can, sir.
I see you're familiar
with the operations
of a class-7 warp drive.
Very familiar, sir.
The Defiant has
an identical engine.
Excellent.
As of this moment,
you are Chief Engineer.
Congratulations.
Chief Engineer?
With rank
of Lieutenant Commander.
Your first assignment
is to figure out
why we can't go
above warp 3.2.
Mr. Parton
believes that--
Excuse me, sir...
I-I don't think
I'm ready for this--
None of us were ready
for the responsibility
thrust upon us, Commander,
but each of us found a way
to rise to the occasion--
do the job that had to be done.
Ready or not...
you are Chief Engineer.
You can do this, Mr. Nog.
Just have faith in yourself,
faith in your shipmates,
and everything'll be fine.
Yes, sir.
I will, sir.
Good man.
That's what
I want to hear.
Now, if you can just fix
our warp drive problems,
we can get on with our mission.
Our mission?
I don't understand.
My orders are to collect
technical data
on a new Dominion battleship
operating in this sector.
We keep picking up
their com traffic
so we know they're in the area
but because we can't go faster
than warp 3.2
we're unable to get
within sensor range.
And Starfleet knows you're
in command of the Valiant.
No.
We've had to maintain
strict radio silence
ever since the war began.
The orders were addressed
to Captain Ramirez.
But since he's dead,
the mission's now mine.
Make no mistake,
I will carry out that mission.
Or die trying.
( sighs )
Dismissed.
Coffee?
Uh, raktajino, please.
Here you go.
Thanks.
So, where are you from?
Me?
Tycho City.
Oh, a Lunar Schooner.
I haven't heard that
in a long time.
Yeah. Picked it up
from my granddad.
Of course, he still calls
Luna "the moon"--
like it's the only one
or something.
Well, nobody who's
ever lived on the moon
calls it Luna either.
That's just something
they say on Earth.
So, what's it like?
You're from Earth,
aren't you?
You've never been
to the moon?
Just never got around to it.
Tell me about it.
Well... people say
it's so barren and harsh
but... it's not.
It's... beautiful.
I mean, Tycho City's
just a city,
but outside, where
the gravity is still low
and there's no air...
You know, the sun only comes up
once a month on the moon.
Every lunar morning, my father
and I would put on suits and...
hike out
across the Sea of Clouds.
We'd stop at this collection
of boulders on the western rim
and... just wait
for the sun to come up.
Dawn is so...
shocking on the moon.
One minute, you're
in the darkest night
you can imagine
and the next instant,
the sun lifts up
and this... glorious pure light
just... explodes
across the surface.
I felt like
I met God every morning.
I'm on duty.
Excuse me.
WATTERS:
What's your solution,
Commander?
I've taken the safeties
off the plasma intercooler
the flux moderator
and the pressure-control system.
That should
solve the problem.
You do realize
you're violating
about 50 safety
regulations?
Yes, sir, I do,
but I also know
Chief O'Brien made
the same changes
to the Defiant.
She never had a problem.
I don't know, Captain.
This seems
kind of risky to me.
Mr. Parton?
After spending seven months
plodding along at warp 3.2,
I'm willing
to try anything, sir.
Watters to Bridge.
Prepare for warp speed.
Aye, sir.
All right, Mr. Nog,
take us to warp 4.
COLLINS:
Can I help
you, sir?
No.
No, I've got it.
Any problems with Sisko's arm?
No, sir.
You got a problem, Chief?
Have you been crying?
( sighs )
A little.
About what?
I was... just...
thinking about home.
Come in.
Chief, I think
you can go now.
Thank you, sir.
FARRIS:
Well, Mr. Sisko
sounds like you
and the Chief
had quite a conversation
this afternoon.
Home and family
and the glories
of dawn on the moon.
Does that just
about cover it?
Yeah, that's, uh...
that's about it.
What's going on?
What's going on, Mr. Sisko,
in case you haven't noticed
is that we are
in the middle of a war.
We can't afford to have
young cadets thinking
about mommy and daddy
when they need to
be concentrating
on their duties.
All I did was ask
about her home.
All you did...
was plunge
a member of this crew
into emotional turmoil.
WATTERS:
Jake...
May I call you Jake?
You're a reporter.
Your job is to watch
the way events unfold
not participate in them.
Right now, you need
to stand back.
Take a look at
where you are--
what's going
on around you.
You're right in the middle
of a great story--
maybe one
of the greatest stories
in the entire Dominion war.
( sighing )
This ship is special, Jake.
This crew is special.
And whatever fates
guide this universe
they've chosen us to achieve
some purpose in this conflict.
I know that.
Just as surely
as I know
your presence
on this ship
is no coincidence.
You're here to write the story--
to tell people
of the Valiant and her crew.
Don't interfere
with the story, Jake.
Don't become a part of it.
Just let it unfold around you.
Observe, listen
and then
write it down.
May I have your word you'll stay
away from Chief Collins?
Okay.
Thank you, Jake.
You're dismissed.
I'm not sure we can trust him.
We'll keep an eye on him.
What about
Mr. Nog?
Mr. Nog wears a uniform.
He'll do his duty.
All right.
That'll be all, Commander.
I'll see you
at 1800 hours.
Yes, sir.
Captain
are you
all right?
Yes. Why?
I heard you were
on the Bridge
during midwatch
again last night.
You haven't been getting
much sleep lately, sir.
None of us have, Commander.
No, sir, I suppose not.
Thank you
for your concern, Karen...
but I'm... I'm fine, really.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry I even brought it up.
That's all right.
( sighing )
Where've you been?
Engine Room.
I solved their warp problem.
What's that?
My Red Squad insignia.
Oh, and in case
you haven't noticed,
this would be my new rank--
Lieutenant Commander Nog,
Chief Engineer.
It has a nice ring to it...
don't you think?
You joined the crew?
Something wrong with that?
It's a little fast.
We just got here
and Watters puts you
in charge of the Engine Room?
Captain Watters is used
to making quick decisions.
He felt I was the right man
for the job, so he promoted me.
Red Alert. All hands
to battle stations.
I repeat, all hands
Range: 1.32 light-years.
Speed: warp 4.7.
What's going on?
We found our
battleship.
HELMSMAN:
Their course is
170 mark 135.
Speed: warp 3.97.
FARRIS:
Bridge to phaser control.
You've got a spike
in the 3-L subsystem.
Take care of it.
Sensors show a drop
in gamma radiation...
...is losing power.
I'll reroute
at the auxiliary
power interface.
HELMSMAN:
They've changed course.
Any sign
they've detected us?
Negative. I think
we're still outside
their sensor range.
Maintain your
distance, Helm.
Match their course and speed.
Aye, sir.
Prepare a class-3 probe
for launch.
Aye, sir.
What happens now?
We're going to launch
a sensor probe to scan
the battleship.
That way, the Valiant
won't be picked up
on their scanners.
Won't they detect a probe?
Class-3 probes
are designed to be
virtually undetectable.
There's almost
no chance of it
being spotted.
JAKE:
Almost?
I don't remember anyone
inviting you to the Bridge.
WATTERS:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51825.4.
We've been shadowing
the Dominion battleship
for three hours.
The data our probe
has gathered so far
has not only been interesting
but it may have given us
a golden opportunity
to strike a blow
for the Federation.
Attention on deck!
Stand at ease.
It's been a long
eight months--
a lot of hard work,
a lot of sacrifice.
And now we've
accomplished
our mission.
We found
the battleship
and obtained a complete scan
without being detected...
and we're free to go home.
But that ship out there
is a direct threat
to every Federation outpost
and colony
within 50 light-years.
That ship must
be destroyed.
( crew murmuring )
It can be destroyed.
Commander?
We found a flaw in the design
of their antimatter
storage system.
The primary support braces
are made of viterium.
It's a very strong,
very resilient metal alloy
which just
happens to become
extremely unstable
when exposed to
delta radiation.
A single torpedo, rigged
with a radiogenic warhead
could reduce those braces
to the consistency of wet pasta.
WATTERS:
As a result,
the entire
antimatter storage system
would tear itself apart.
Commander Nog.
You don't seem convinced.
Well, sir, in-in order
to rig a torpedo
to yield
a delta radiation burst,
I'll have to remove
most of the guidance systems.
We'll have
to target it manually.
FARRIS:
We've trained for
that possibility.
It shouldn't be a problem.
We'll also have to get
very close to the target.
How close?
Within 300 meters.
( crew murmuring )
It's dangerous,
there's no disputing that.
And no one would think
any less of us
if we just turn around
and go home.
But that means
that some other ship
with some other crew
would be asked
to finish the job
that we started.
I think we can do it.
I think we should do it.
Can I say something?
You are not a member
of this crew.
Let him speak.
You all probably know
who my father is.
Benjamin Sisko?
So you know I'm not exaggerating
when I say that he's considered
to be one of the best
combat officers in the fleet,
and I'm telling you
right now
that even with the entire crew
of the Defiant with him,
my father would never try
to pull off something like this.
And if he can't do it,
it can't be done.
We're Red Squad
and we can do anything.
CREW:
Yeah! Red Squad!
( chanting ):
Red Squad! Red Squad!
Red Squad!
JAKE:
This is suicide.
No. It's not.
Nog, listen to me.
We're in way
over our heads here.
Now, someone told me
that ship out there
is twice the size
of a Galaxy-class ship...
and three times as strong.
That's accurate.
And you really think we can go
up against a ship like that?
I think that
Captain Watters knows...
what he's doing.
Oh, really?
Well, uh, did you know
that Watters has been taking
cordafin stimulants
for the past two months?
Where did you
hear that?
Dorian told me.
You were ordered
to stay away from her.
Watters to Shepard.
Please report
to my ready room, Lieutenant.
That's not the way we
do things in Starfleet.
I can't believe
you're buying everything
that Watters is selling.
He's not selling anything.
He's reminding
us of our duty.
I feel like
I'm having a conversation
with one of the bulkheads.
You don't understand
because you've never put on
one of these uniforms.
You don't know
anything about
sacrifice or honor
or duty or any other things
that make up a soldier's life.
I'm part of something
larger than myself.
All you care about is you.
That's right.
All I care about is Jake Sisko
and whether or not he's going
to be killed
by a bunch
of delusional fanatics
looking for martyrdom.
Get out.
I don't even know
who you are anymore.
I'm the Chief Engineer
of the Starship Valiant.
I'll have them put that
on your tombstone.
Mr. Sisko!
I'm afraid you'll have
to miss all the fun.
You're going to spend the rest
of this mission in the brig.
FARRIS:
All decks report
ready, sir.
This is the Captain.
We are about
to engage the enemy.
For the last eight months,
I've told you to stay
focused on one thing--
your duty.
But now I want you
to step back from your duty
and take a look around,
and I don't mean
look at the walls.
I want you to look
at this moment in your life.
Take it in.
Appreciate the fact
that you are on this ship
with this group of people,
at this point in history.
But understand one thing
above all else.
This moment
will never come again.
Hold on to it.
Savor it for as long as you can.
You're Starfleet,
you're Red Squad,
and you're the best.
Now...
let's get that battleship
and we can all go home.
Captain out.
( com beep )
All right then.
Good luck.
Take us to warp 6, Mr. Nog.
Warp six.
Aye.
They've spotted us.
They're dropping
out of warp.
Helm, go to impulse.
Aye, sir.
We are in visual range.
On screen.
Lay in a strafing course
along their superstructure
and make it close.
That way, they won't get
a weapons lock on us.
I want to scrape some paint
off their hull, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Raise shields, charge phasers,
fire at any targets
of opportunity as we pass.
Aye, sir.
Torpedo status?
Torpedoes ready, sir.
Defense system ready.
Helm ready.
All right, Mr. Shepard,
take us in.
Shields holding.
Course stable.
Fire at will!
( yelling )
WATTERS:
Helm! Hard about!
Tactical, get a target lock
on those braces!
NOG:
Impulse engines
at full thrust.
They're trying
to jam our sensors.
WATTERS:
Mr. Nog, initiate
countermeasures.
I'm on it!
I've acquired the target.
Torpedoes locked!
Full power to forward shields.
Helm, plot an escape course
down the z-axis.
Ready.
Engage.
They're turning to port.
Match them, Helm.
Keep us on track.
Aye, sir.
Hull breach on Deck Two.
Emergency force-fields
are in place.
FARRIS:
Steady our course, Helm.
I can't maintain targeting lock.
Karen!
It's all yours.
Fire when ready.
Understood.
Just a little closer.
We're losing our port shields.
Steady as she goes.
Torpedoes away.
Aft view on screen!
( cheering )
Did we miss the target?
No, sir.
It was a direct hit.
It just...
It didn't work.
Orders, Captain?
Lay in a new course.
127 mark 3--
Hull breach on Deck Two.
Deck Three,
Deck Four...
Evasive maneuvers.
Bring us about to
course 127 mark 320!
I've lost helm control!
Main power's off-line!
I'm rerouting the...
( yelling )
Auxiliary power's off-line.
But I still have phaser control.
Shall I return fire?
Sir?!
No, it's over.
The Captain wanted us--
The Captain
is dead, Chief.
They're all dead.
The ship is lost.
There's no need
for us to die here, too.
( alarm blaring )
COMPUTER:
Abandon ship. Abandon ship.
This is not a drill.
All hands proceed
to emergency escape pods.
Hey!
Somebody let me out of here!
Help!
Jake, Jake!
What happened?
We failed.
Captain, I'm picking up
a Starfleet distress signal.
Bearing: 318 mark 005.
Range: ten light-years.
That location is inside
Dominion-held space.
Can you identify the ship
sending the distress call?
Looks like it's coming
from an escape pod.
USS... Valiant.
The Valiant
was reported missing
over eight months ago.
It could be
a Dominion ruse
to lure us
into their territory.
Then again,
it may be genuine.
We have to find out.
Cloak the ship
and lay in a course.
KIRA:
Aye, sir.
We scanned the area
for any other escape pods,
but it doesn't look like
anyone else made it.
It was a long shot.
I just thought maybe...
( door opens )
How is she, Doctor?
I've managed to repair
her fractured skull
and with a little rest,
she should be fine.
And Nog?
Oh, a few bumps
and bruises,
but he's going
to be fine as well.
Can I talk to him?
I don't see why not.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
You going to write
a story about all this?
Probably.
What are you
going to say?
What do you think
I should say?
That it was a good ship...
with a good crew...
that made a mistake.
We...
let ourselves blindly follow
Captain Watters...
and he led us
over a cliff.
That's not true.
Captain Watters was a great man.
Dorian...
he got everyone killed.
If he failed,
it's because we failed him.
Put that in your story, too.
Let people read it
and decide for themselves.
He may have been a hero...
he may even have been
a great man...
but in the end,
he was a bad Captain.