I am truly impressed,
and I'm not easily impressed.
In all my years as the
proprietor of Quark's Bar
Grill, Gaming House
and Holosuite Arcade
I have never seen such a glowing
employee performance report.
I mean, look at this.
In three months,
no customer has filed
a single complaint against you.
You haven't spilled a drink,
mixed up a food order
or shortchanged a bill.
I take my job very seriously.
And, yet, you always manage
to wear a friendly smile.
That's because I like my work.
I'm happy to be here.
And it shows.
The customers love you.
Your fellow dabo girls
love you.
Even the Ferengi waiters
sing your praises
and you know why?
Because you're nice.
I try to be.
You're nice to the customers.
You're nice to the dabo girls.
You're nice
to the Ferengi waiters.
You're nice to everyone...
almost everyone.
You mean, I've offended someone?
Look closely, Aluura.
Can't you see
the pain in my eyes?
But I'm always nice to you.
I think you could be nicer.
How much nicer?
Oo-mox for Fun and Profit?
It's a quick read.
Oh...
you... want me to be...
nice.
Let's face it.
The customers, the dabo
girls, the Ferengi waiters...
they didn't hire you
and, uh...
they can't fire you.
You wouldn't.
Would you?
Read the book.
Brother...
we need to talk.
Go away.
I'm in the middle of a meeting.
But it's important.
So is this meeting.
It's about our mother.
How many times have I told you
not to mention Moogie
when I'm... working?
Sorry
but I tried contacting
her this morning
and I couldn't get through.
She's probably off
visiting the Grand Nagus.
I tried the Tower of Commerce.
There was no answer
there either.
They're probably on vacation.
Now, leave me alone.
I'm trying to concentrate.
Brother, you don't understand.
I can't get a hold of
anyone on Ferenginar...
not Cousin Gaila, not Lek.
I tell you, something's
very wrong.
All right.
We will continue this later.
In the meantime,
you have some reading to do.
Hello, Aluura.
She's so nice.
We'll see.
A Dominion invasion
of Ferenginar?
Think of the terrible
repercussions
to the Alpha Quadrant.
I cannot think of any.
How could the Dominion
invade Ferenginar
without first conquering
the surrounding systems
like Clarus and Irtok?
Brother, did you hear that?
They've captured Irtok, as well.
That's not what I said.
There are no reports
of Dominion activity
anywhere near that sector.
Why can't we get through
to Ferenginar?
Moogie, the Nagus,
Cousin Gaila...
they're all dead.
You don't know that,
Rom, but something
is definitely wrong
on Ferenginar.
We'll see
what we can find out.
Captain
a Ferengi ship is
approaching the station
requesting permission
to dock.
It's Grand Nagus Zek...
and your mother is with him.
They're alive!
Nice work.
Quark, Rom!
It's good to see you boys.
It's good to see you,
too, Nagus.
Come along, my dear.
Moogie...
I was so worried.
You're a good son.
I was worried, too.
And you're a good liar.
Moogie, do you think
it's a good idea
to be wearing
clothes in public?
He's right.
What if one
of my Ferengi waiters sees you?
I hope they do.
Tell them, Zekkie.
No, you go right ahead,
my dear.
No, it should really
come from you.
Would someone please tell me
what's going on?
It's one of those
good news/bad news
type of things.
Give him the good news first.
If you insist.
Three days ago,
I added a new amendment
to the Ferengi Bill
of Opportunities
giving females
the right to wear clothes.
In public?
Anywhere we want.
That can't be the good news.
If Ferengi females
can wear clothes in public
then they can leave their homes.
If they can leave their homes,
they can go to work.
If they go to work,
they can make profit.
What's the matter, Quark...
afraid of a little competition?
Are you sure
that's the good news?
It sounds good to me.
Oh, now you see
why I like him best?
Face it, Quark...
it's good business.
For thousands of years,
Ferenginar has allowed
a valuable resource
to go to waste.
Females...
a valuable resource?
They make up 53.5 percent
of the population
and contribute
virtually nothing
to gross planetary income.
I say it's time they started
pulling their own weight.
Better tell me the bad news.
It might cheer me up.
I doubt it.
The moment fully clothed females
started appearing
on the streets of Ferenginar
financial chaos erupted
all over the planet.
That explains
the communications blackout.
There was so much
buying and selling
throughout the Alliance
that the entire planetary
communications grid shut down.
If there's trouble
on Ferenginar
what are you doing here?
I've been deposed.
I'm no longer Grand Nagus.
Then who is?
Who do you think?
Brunt.
Grand Nagus Brunt?
Acting Grand Nagus Brunt.
Brother, we're in trouble now.
Brunt hates us.
Well, don't start panicking.
The Ferengi Commerce Authority
hasn't confirmed him yet.
And they won't
for three more days.
Boys, together we're going
to reconquer an empire
or die in the attempt!
What lovely quarters
you have, Quark.
Small... but lovely.
As of this moment
I declare this site
to be the headquarters
of the sole legitimate
government of Ferenginar.
I still can't believe it.
Brunt is the new Nagus?
Acting Nagus.
For three more days.
Then it becomes official.
I'm not worried.
I have a secret weapon...
your mother.
Now, here's the plan:
One, we contact
every FCA Commissioner
and invite them to the station
for a meeting.
Two, Ishka runs the meeting.
Oh, they'll love that.
Maybe not at first,
but she'll win them over
using her vast
financial knowledge
and her keen instinct
for profit.
She'll prove once and for all
that allowing
females to wear clothing
is the first step
toward a healthier
and more prosperous
Ferengi economy.
And three...
What was three again, my dear?
The FCA Commissioners
reinstate you as Nagus.
And who could ask
for a happier ending than that?
But that's only the beginning,
lobekins.
I predict that one day
a female will enter
the Tower of Commerce
climb the 40 flights of stairs
to the Chamber of Opportunity
and take her rightful place
as Grand Nagus
of the Ferengi Alliance.
Don't look at me.
It was your amendment.
Nagus, you remember
my son, Nog, don't you?
He's the first Ferengi
to join Starfleet.
I'll try not to hold that
against him.
And this is my wife, Leeta.
I've heard...
so much about you.
Would you like to hear more?
Remember, she's Rom's wife.
Meaning what?
Meaning she's broke.
She doesn't look broke
to me.
Zekkie...
Just having
a little harmless fun,
my sweet.
Now, Quark,
you and your brother
get rid of some
of this furniture
and, you, get three
subspace transceivers off my
ship and set them up in here.
And where's my beetle snuff?
Grand Nagus Brunt.
Good afternoon, I'm calling
on behalf of Grand Nagus Zek.
The Nagus summons you
to a meeting here
on Deep Space 9.
He's counting on your support.
You'll be presented with some
very interesting financial data.
There's profit to be earned.
And the Nagus wants you
to share
in these lucrative
opportunities.
Yes, I'm talking
about the Grand Nagus.
No, not Brunt.
Grand Nagus Zek.
Who said he was dead?
Wait.
Don't end the transmission.
Hello? Hello?
Where'd he go?
I know all about the 94th Rule
of Acquisition.
I know... females and finances
don't mix.
But that can be interpreted
in many different ways.
Hello? Hello?
That's not a very nice thing
to say about the Nagus.
I beg your pardon?
There's no need to be insulting.
Hello?
Hello? Hello?
That female
happens to be my mother!
Hello?
Are you sure you contacted
every Commissioner on this list?
All 432 of them.
And you could only convince
one of them to attend a meeting?
Maybe if we made some
follow-up calls.
I helped every one
of those people earn a fortune!
And this is how they repay me?
What a bunch of ingrates.
Well, the news isn't all bad.
The Commissioner
who's agreed to come...
it's Nilva.
The Chairman of Slug-o-Cola.
He's a very powerful
and influential voice
within the FCA.
Unfortunately, he's
an influential voice
for the status quo.
I don't think Slug-o-Cola
has changed its advertising
slogan in 300 years.
Drink Slug-o-Cola
...the slimiest cola
in the galaxy.
Why would Nilva agree
to come to the meeting?
I'm not sure, but if I can
convince him to support Zek
other Commissioners will follow.
Well, it's a start, at least.
See? I told you
it was too early to panic.
Care to place a wager
on that?
Grand Nagus Brunt!
Acting Grand Nagus Brunt.
Now you can panic.
I'll take an Eelwasser.
No ice.
What are you doing here, Brunt?
That's Grand Nagus Brunt.
Acting Grand Nagus.
Would someone
please tell that female
to take off those clothes?
It's disgusting.
Get used to it, limp lobes.
This is the future.
Over my dead body.
If that's what it takes.
I don't suppose you're
here to reminisce
about the time you helped
my brother and me
rescue Moogie from the Dominion.
You're right,
that's not why I'm here.
Though I find it ironic
that helping
to rescue your mother
was the first step
on my road to becoming Nagus.
Don't remind me.
I never should have
given you your job back
with the FCA.
But you did.
And as a liquidator,
I was able to bribe my way
back into a position of power.
That is ironic.
Face it, Zek.
It's over.
You're finished...
bankrupt.
I'm going to liquidate you.
Cancel that Eelwasser.
And get me a...
Slug-o-Cola instead.
On second thought...
I'll just wait till
Chairman Nilva gets here.
I'm sure he'll be happy
to provide his new Nagus
with all the Slug-o-Cola
I can drink.
How did you know
Nilva was coming here?
Because it's my business
to know.
Go on.
Have your little meeting.
Whatever you offer
Nilva, I'll double it.
That's it!
Get out of my bar.
You dare threaten your Nagus?
Acting Nagus.
You may liquidate us tomorrow
but right now,
this is still my establishment.
Now, get out
before I kick you out.
I'm going to make you a pauper.
Uri'lash... we're leaving.
Say good-bye
to these poor people.
Out.
My boy, I'm proud of you.
So am I.
Me, too.
I just kicked the Grand
Nagus out of my bar.
Acting Grand Nagus.
Whatever.
I need to lie down.
You busy, Quark?
Busy?
Me?
Nah. I'm just lying here
wondering if it's not too late
for me to start
a new life somewhere.
Oh, Quark, there's nothing wrong
with your life.
I'm sorry.
I stand corrected.
You're overreacting.
Whatever you say.
Reminds me of when
you were a lobling.
You were always
such a miserable child.
Moogie, leave me alone.
I'm your mother;
I can't leave you alone.
Try!
Come on, on your feet.
Zekkie's waiting for you
in the bar.
Now what?
He feels like playing
a game of tongo.
We're all facing banishment
from Ferengi society
and he wants to play tongo?
He wants to play tongo.
I want to have
a late-night snack.
You want to lie here,
feeling sorry for yourself.
We all deal with stress
in different ways.
Any fresh tube grubs around?
How can you eat
at a time like this?
It's simple.
You put one end of the tube grub
between your front teeth
and you suck them right up.
You want tube grubs?
Fine.
Enjoy.
These are minced.
I wanted fresh.
You know, this is
all your fault.
It's my fault
you don't have fresh tube grubs?
I'm not talking
about tube grubs.
I'm talking
about Ferengi females
wearing clothes
and earning profit.
I'm talking
about Grand Nagus Brunt.
Acting Grand Nagus Brunt!
You're not fooling me, Moogie.
You've been plotting
this all along.
Ever since you met Zek
you've been working on him
manipulating him,
whispering things in his ears
things like "Equality
for Females."
What's wrong with that?
I'll tell you
what's wrong with that.
You've ruined Zek's life,
your life, Rom's life.
As if you cared about any of us.
It's your life
you're worried about.
You bet I'm worried.
Nobody else seems to care
what happens to me.
You come here to my station
take over my quarters,
make me
a part of your
subversive schemes...
What's the matter, Quark?
Are you afraid
you picked the wrong side?
You can always
go crawling to Brunt,
beg his forgiveness.
I don't want anything
to do with Brunt.
I want my old Nagus back!
Do you.
I want Zek to be
the way he used to be
before he met you,
before you twisted his thinking
with your-your...
your feminine wiles.
Before he met me, Zek was
a lonely, unhappy man.
But he was rich!
He was the most powerful
Ferengi alive.
Now what is he?
A puppet.
And you're the one
pulling the strings
making him dance
to your evil feminist tune.
You're the worst thing
that ever happened to Zek!
that ever happened to me.
In fact, you're the worst thing
that ever happened
to the entire Ferengi Alliance!
Maybe I am!
But at least I'm not like you.
A selfish, spineless,
ungrateful...
Don't forget miserable.
Miserable excuse for a son!
Is that the best you can do?
I haven't even begun.
You should be
ashamed of yourself.
Why, you are nothing but a...
why, you are... you...
Go ahead. Say it.
You're a...
I'm still waiting.
You're a... you're a...
A... what?!
Moogie...
Moogie? Moogie!
Moogie?
Moogie? Moogie?
Moogie...
please don't die.
She's not going to die.
She's going to get better.
I hope so... for my sake...
for her sake...
for the sake of the entire
Ferengi Alliance,
and most of all
I hope she gets better
for your sake, Quark
because if she doesn't...
What did I do?
That's exactly the question
I keep asking myself!
What did you do to her?!
I told you.
She said she was hungry.
I gave her some tube grubs.
She thanked me...
and then she collapsed.
I wish you'd stop
making me relive it.
Are you sure you didn't
do or say anything
that might have upset her?
I don't want to
talk about it anymore.
What's wrong, Quark?
Your conscience bothering you?
I haven't done anything wrong.
That's not
what your mother says.
Doctor... how's Moogie?
Will she live?
Oh, yes, she'll live.
She needed a new heart,
and it's functioning normally
but she's going to need
a few days complete rest.
And she'll need to be kept
far away from him.
And why is that, Doctor?
I'm not sure exactly.
All I do know
is that she keeps repeating
the same phrase over and over:
"It's all Quark's fault.
It's all Quark's fault."
I wonder what she means by that.
And, uh... then I...
I accused her of being
the worst thing that ever
happened to the Ferengi Alliance
and she clutched her chest
and collapsed.
Moogie and I argue all the time.
It's our way
of showing affection.
Well, if you ask me, Quark,
the worst thing
that ever happened
to the Ferengi Alliance is you.
I'm sorry.
Well, I suppose we
should contact Nilva
and tell him the meeting
has to be postponed.
We can't postpone the meeting!
In two days, the FCA
is going to confirm Brunt
as the new Grand Nagus.
Boy, when things go wrong...
The only thing to do
is to get down on your knees
and beg for mercy.
Who knows?
You might find me
in a charitable mood.
By the time
I get through with you
you're the one
who's going to need charity.
Such brave words...
yet so empty.
I was very relieved
to hear your mother
is going to be all right.
Of course,
it doesn't do you much good.
Nilva will be arriving tonight
expecting to meet
a brilliant Ferengi female.
Do you know any?
I mean, besides Ishka?
I certainly don't.
How...
pitiful.
One day you're the Grand Nagus
of the Ferengi Alliance,
and the next
you're nothing but a
common barroom brawler.
You see what happens
when you put your
faith in a female?
What about Leeta?
What about her?
Maybe she could
meet with Nilva.
She handles my finances,
and she's a female.
And a very beautiful one
at that.
But Nilva's expecting
to meet with a Ferengi female.
We'll never get one here
in time.
We're doomed.
No, we're not.
You think if Ishka were here,
she'd give up?
If she were here, we
wouldn't have a problem.
That's not my point.
Your mother
would never accept defeat.
If she couldn't find
another female, she'd...
she'd... she'd...
She'd what?
She'd make one.
You mean a hologram?
Better than a hologram.
What could be better
than a hologram?
You.
Dr. Bashir certainly did
a wonderful job on you.
I'd call the operation
a complete success.
It must've been a
very delicate procedure.
Tell me about it.
There.
Well, how do I look?
You look nice.
Nice?
That's all?
Very nice.
You may look like a female
but you have to do something
about that voice.
I'm trying!
I-I mean... I'm trying.
Well, try harder.
And stop looking down.
I need to see
what I look like.
Someone get me a mirror.
You see, Brother?
You look lovely.
There go his hormones.
You mean her hormones?
Ta-take it away!
Take it away!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just feel so-so different.
Would you stop staring
at your chest?
I'm not staring at my chest.
I'm staring at my hips.
Aren't they too big?
Your hips are fine.
Now, let's get
down to business.
These are your mother's notes
for her meeting with Nilva.
Study them carefully.
"Female apparel for
a new source of latinum
"for a new Ferenginar.
"Hypicate cream
for smooth skin
and healthier profits."
All these facts and figures...
they're too much
for me to remember.
Oh, nonsense.
You just need a little time
to practice your presentation.
And while you're at it
we need to practice
your walk.
What's wrong with my walk?
You're... lumbering.
This is never going to work.
Don't cry, Brother.
Here. Let me show you.
Watch carefully.
You see, it's more of a glide.
That's... good.
And when you sit, make sure
your knees are touching
and don't forget
to relax your shoulders
but keep your bottom tight.
What?
He's the one
that should be
wearing the dress.
Why me?
You're so adorable...
and... complicated.
Maybe it's not too late.
Come on, Brother,
I'll take you to Dr. Bashir.
Forget it, Quark.
Rom may make
a better female than you
but when it comes to business,
you're the better Ferengi.
Looks like your stupidity
has saved you again.
It comes in handy sometimes.
I can do this.
It's only one meeting.
I can be a female
for one meeting...
can't I?
Not if you're lumbering.
I'll conduct the
meeting sitting down.
Tighten your bottom.
Well, I think you're
doing wonderfully, my dear.
I'm proud of you.
I'm sorry.
You know,
you may walk like a man
but you make
a very attractive female.
Confusing, isn't it?
Not to me.
He's here.
He's on the station.
Who is?
Nilva.
But he's not supposed
to arrive until tomorrow.
That Nilva, he's a tricky one
but he makes a good cola.
What do we do?
No, I-I can't meet Nilva now.
I'm still lumbering.
You look very nice.
Nog, I want you
to escort the chairman
to his quarters.
Tell him I'll meet him
for dinner tonight.
Yeah.
Oh, what if he asks about Ishka?
Tell him that Ishka is sick
but that, tomorrow,
he'll be meeting
with my other female
financial advisor...
uh... uh...
Lumba.
Right.
Lumba?
You'd better start memorizing
those notes.
First, we need
to practice your walking.
And your sitting.
And you'd better work
on that voice.
Any other comments?
Has anyone ever told you
that you have lovely eyes?
Here.
Have a Slug-o-Cola.
Thank you.
Welcome to Deep Space 9,
Chairman Nilva.
You drink Slug-o-Cola,
don't you?
The slimiest cola in the galaxy?
Doesn't everybody?
Good boy.
Now, take me to Zek.
Zek wanted me to take you to...
Oh, don't argue with me.
Drink your cola
and lead the way.
Um... uh...
Uh...
You sure you don't want
to stop by your quarters
and freshen up?
Not before I meet
this female advisor of Zek's.
Nilva, how nice
to see you again.
Grand Nagus Brunt.
Acting Grand Nagus Brunt.
Well, I had a feeling
I might find you here.
I thought
after your meeting with Zek
we could have a little chat.
Oh, of course.
But I've really come
to meet this Ishka female.
Haven't you heard?
Ishka's in the Infirmary.
She's in no position
to meet anyone.
Which is why you'll be meeting
with another one of Zek's
financial advisors.
Her name is Lumba.
Never heard of her.
Oh, Zek has two female advisors?
I didn't know there were
two Ferengi females
on the station.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's go meet this other female.
Are you sure you
wouldn't like me
to show you around
the station first?
I want to meet Lumba.
Lumba?
Let's try it again.
My name is Lumba.
You must be Chairman Nilva.
Zek has told me
so much about you...
Ow!
What's wrong now?
It's these earrings,
they're killing me.
Do I have to wear them?
No woman is complete
without earrings.
Why does everyone
keep looking at me?
I'm going to bed.
Now?
I'm exhausted.
If I don't get any sleep
I'll never make it through
tomorrow's meeting.
Who could that be?
Come in.
Nilva!
Zek!
Here. Have a Slug-o-Cola.
Oh, don't worry.
I brought enough for everyone.
He insisted on seeing
you immediately.
Why, you must be Lunga.
Lumba.
Oh, a clothed female Ferengi...
and with your approval, no less.
Oh, either you've been
inhaling too much beetle snuff
or you're the greatest
visionary ever to sit atop
the Tower of Commerce.
Well, uh,
why don't you and I have
dinner tonight
and try to figure it out?
We can go to Quark's
and get some nice
juicy snail steaks.
You can meet
with Lumba tomorrow.
I'm afraid that's not possible.
You see, I have to leave
first thing in the morning.
I'm due back on Ferenginar
for an important
stockholder's meeting.
Oh, but those snail steaks
do sound tempting.
I know.
Why don't I have
dinner with Lumba?
Oh, with me?
Won't you feel uncomfortable
being seen
in public with a clothed female?
Well, of course, I will
but you and I have earned
a lot of latinum
together over the years.
That should be worth
some small discomfort.
But Lumba better be
all you claim she is
or I'll have
to liquidate you myself.
Here. Let's eat.
Have fun.
Two snail steaks,
lightly seared.
Now, tell me something.
Doesn't wearing
all those clothes
make you feel like a deviant?
Not really.
And I'll tell you why.
Because, under all these clothes
I know I'm totally naked.
I'll try to remember that.
Now, you'd better explain to me
how allowing females
to wear clothing
is going to make me richer
than I already am.
I was hoping you were
going to ask me that.
You see this dress
I'm wearing?
Have you any idea
how much it would sell
for on Ferenginar?
Would someone please tell
me what they're saying?
- Shh!
Let me see if I understand.
Giving females the right
to wear clothing
allows them to... have pockets.
Once they have pockets
they're going to want
to fill them with latinum.
Which means they're going
to need jobs.
And once
they start earning latinum
they're going
to want to spend it.
Which means,
Ferenginar will be expanding
its workforce
and its consumer base
at the same time.
Oh, there will be plenty
of profit for everyone.
When it comes to profit,
I'm your girl.
And... I'm sure you could use
a little extra latinum.
Meaning what?
I read the beverage trades.
Sales of Slug-o-Cola
have flattened out
and Eelwasser
had a very impressive
third quarter.
Aw, they were lucky.
That's all.
I know a way
you can increase sales
of Slug-o-Cola
by 50 to 60 percent.
I'm all ears.
Target the new female consumer.
Make Slug-o-Cola her drink.
There's nothing stopping her
from drinking it now.
But you're
not encouraging her either.
"The slimiest cola
in the galaxy"?
That kind of slogan
doesn't appeal to women.
Well, what would?
Let me see.
Slug-o-Cola contains
43 percent live algae, right?
In every bottle.
Well, how about something like
"Drink Slug-o-Cola...
and keep...
your teeth
that lovely shade of green"?
Oh...
Zek was right about you.
You're very intelligent.
For a female.
I think it's time
for dessert now.
Good idea.
I thought we were going
to have dessert.
Oh, we are...
in my quarters.
Oh, I never ever thought
I'd find a clothed
female so... enticing.
Enticing?
Me?
Don't be silly.
It's so good
to finally be alone...
without all those
people staring at us.
Although, I must admit
I-I did find it
somewhat stimulating.
Maybe a little too stimulating.
Oh, can I help it
if my lobes burn
for you, huh, huh?
If you don't believe me,
just touch them.
Touch them.
I'll take your word for it.
You said you'd do
anything for me.
I lied.
Oh, oh, oh...
Oh, come to me,
my little love slave.
Ah!
Yeah, yeah!
Stay away!
Stay away, stay away.
Ha!
Marry me.
I don't think your
wife would approve.
Who cares? She hasn't
touched my lobes in months.
I can tell.
Oh, I need you.
What you need is a cold shower!
What a good idea.
Why, you can scrub my back.
- What if...
- Yes?
I told you...
Yes?
I hate Slug-o-Cola?
Oh, so do I!
Oh, you torture me.
Stay away...
Stay away?
- Or...
- Or what?
Or I'll jump.
I'll catch you.
Let go of that man!
I'm trying.
Would you please leave?
You're making Lumba nervous.
His name's not Lumba,
it's Quark
and he's a male.
A male?
How pitiful.
Zek must be truly desperate.
Is this true?
You're... a man?
Do I look like a man?
Nice try, Quark,
but it's not going to work.
He's the station's
bartender.
Don't listen to him,
hot lobes.
I'm as female as they come
and I'm going
to prove it to you.
Well?
Well, I'm... not sure.
Oh...
all right.
Now are you sure?
Oh... completely.
I tell you
that is not a female!
Well, she's close enough
for me.
Oh, come, my dear.
Let's go tell Zek
that I'm going to do
everything in my power
to make sure
he remains Grand Nagus.
But...
why?
Because that's what Lumba wants.
His name's Quark.
Interesting ring.
It was a gift.
Poor Nilva...
such a lovely man but so lonely.
Really?
There was a sweetness to him...
and also a strength.
Sometimes, he'd get
this little glint in his eye...
You know what I mean.
Not really...
but I'm glad you had
a pleasant evening.
You're mocking me, aren't you?
And you're being
a little overly sensitive.
I've only been a male again
for six hours.
My hormones must still be
out of balance.
My emotions are raging
out of control.
Is there anything I can do?
Would you mind...
giving me... a hug?
A hug?
Just a small one.
Thank you!
I hope we're not
interrupting anything.
Uh, excuse me.
We just wanted
to say good-bye
before we go back
to Ferenginar.
Where the rivers run with muck
and the streets
are swarming with happy females.
And where, if all
goes according to plan
the FCA Commissioners
will once again
proclaim me Grand Nagus.
That would be nice, but Brunt's
going to fight
you at every turn.
Ah, I wouldn't have
it any other way.
I'm glad we have
Nilva on our side
and we have you
to thank for that, Quark.
Will you forgive me, Moogie?
Of course I do.
You may be a lousy son
but you made
a wonderful daughter.
I hope the experience
taught you something.
It made me more compassionate
more empathetic,
more nurturing.
I feel like I'm trapped
in my worst nightmare.
Don't worry.
I'm sure it won't last.
You'll be back to your
old self in no time.
Mmm...
You are so... lucky.
Oh.
No man ever gave me a ring.
Quark?
Aluura...
I read the book.
What book?
You know, Oo-mox for Fun...
You shouldn't be
wasting your time
reading that kind of trash.
But you told me to...
Forget what I told you.
It was wrong and I apologize.
You are a wonderful employee
and I'm lucky
to have you working for me.
In fact, as of today,
I'm giving you a raise...
another two slips
of latinum a week.
Really?
It's the least I can do.
That's too bad.
All right, make it three.
No, it's not that.
Then what?
It's just that...
oo-mox sounded like fun...
the tympanic tickle
the eustachian tube rub
the... auditory nerve nibble...
But if that's the way
you feel about it...
That is exactly
the way I feel about it.
What am I saying?
Aluura?
Wait.