Wake up.
It's time to go.
Hmm?
( sighs ):
Hi, honey.
It's almost 7:00,
time to get ready.
( chuckles )
Time to get ready for what?
The picnic.
( sighs )
What picnic?
Is that today?
Yes, don't you remember?
Oh, well, we better
get going then.
I'm going to wear
my blue jumper.
Oh, good idea,
sweetie.
I can't believe
how much she's grown
since I saw her last.
Mm. Look who's talking.
What?
What have you
been eating
since we've been gone?
Well, the usual.
Well, say good-bye
to the usual.
I'm back and you're going
to start eating right.
Can't it wait
till after the picnic?
No.
Mommy,
can you help me put this on?
Of course, sweetie.
O'BRIEN:
Where's the sunscreen?
I've already packed it.
This is where we're
going, Yoshi. See?
Last time we went to Golana
you were inside
Mommy's tummy.
Better get down
to the airlock.
The shuttle leaves
in 20 minutes.
Can we bring Chester?
I don't think that would be
a good idea, sweetie.
He might get lost.
On second thought...
All right, let's go.
Come on, Lupi.
No sausages?
I know what I'm going
to be when I grow up.
You do?
Mm-hmm.
I'm going to be
an exo-bologist.
An exo-bologist?
What's that?
Someone who
studies animals
from other planets.
Like Chester.
( chuckles )
Daddy, if you send
us away again
can we take Chester?
Honey, I'm not going
to send you away again.
You're not?
No, I'm not.
I only did it
because it wasn't
safe for you
to be on the station.
I know.
We're never going
to be apart again.
Promise?
I promise.
You want to see me
do some cartwheels?
You bet!
Wow!
Yay! Good one!
( chuckling )
Whoa!
Ah! And what about you,
little fella, huh?
What do you say?
( Yoshi babbles )
I couldn't have said
it better myself.
Ah, real sunshine.
Fresh air.
You and the kids.
Life doesn't get
any better than this.
That was a pretty
big promise
you made Molly
just a second ago.
I meant it.
What if the war heats up
and the station
isn't safe anymore?
I'll put in for a transfer.
I never want us
to be apart again.
( Molly screaming )
Molly?!
Molly!
( screaming )
Molly?!
Daddy! Help!
Molly!
Molly, I'm coming!
Daddy!
Hold on, Molly. Hold on.
Daddy's coming. Come on.
Daddy, help.
Take my hand.
Come on, just... take my hand.
( screaming )
( muted voices )
Keiko.
Have you figured out
what this thing is yet?
( sighs )
It's some sort
of time portal.
From the chroniton
signature
we think it sent Molly...
back about 300 years
into the past.
Ah.
I wonder what
this place was like
three centuries ago.
Odo contacted the Bajoran
Archaeological Institute
to see what he
could find out.
Well, how do we
get Molly back?
Well, first...
we have to find a way
to reactivate the portal.
It's been abandoned
a long time
and it was destabilized
when Molly fell through.
The problem is,
we're not sure
how this technology works.
Well, something tells me
the Chief isn't going to stop
until he figures it out.
Something tells me
you're right.
Assuming you get this
back on line, what then?
We punch a transport
scanning beam
through the portal,
and then we try to lock on
to Molly's
DNA signature.
And pull her back
into the present.
That's the idea.
Oh!
Oh, bollocks!
( Yoshi crying )
KEIKO:
Shh, it's all right,
sweetie.
Shh. It's all right.
Maybe you should take
him up to the Defiant.
It might be too cold
in here for him.
I'm not
going anywhere.
I'll take him.
Yeah, come on.
It's going to be
all right, Yoshi.
It's going to
be all right.
You're okay, sweetie.
Come on.
( crying continues )
Give me a hand here.
Okay.
( humming )
Oh, yes, oh, yes, I know.
Mm-hmm.
You're very good
with him.
He knows me.
I had him inside of
me for five months.
Oh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
Oh, I know.
I think...
I think I might
want to have
one of my own someday.
According to the archaeologists
I talked to
the portal was built
by a civilization
that vanished 2000 years ago.
Which means...
if Molly survived the fall
she would have
found herself all alone.
You're saying that the planet
was uninhabited 300 years ago?
The first Bajoran colonists
didn't arrive
till the turn of the century.
An eight-year-old girl
stranded alone
on a deserted planet.
Poor Molly.
With any luck
the Chief will be able
to beam her out
a few minutes after she fell.
She'll hardly know
she was gone.
Miles...
I'm getting scared.
You've been
at it all day.
( sighs )
Just tell me you're
getting closer.
I think I've found
a way to modulate
the temporal field generators.
If it works...
Molly'll be home
in a few hours.
She's just been
looking forward
to coming out here
ever since I told her
we were coming
back to the station.
Where's our baby?
Shh... shh...
Dear, come on.
Come on.
We're going
to get her back.
Everything's going
to be all right.
Dax to O'Brien.
Go ahead.
DAX: The power converter
you asked me to reconfigure--
it's ready to go on line.
What? What's that mean?
It means Molly's
coming home.
Come on.
Transporter interface link.
Synchronized.
DNA acquisition sensors.
Locked in.
We're as ready as we're
ever gonna be, Chief.
Okay.
Let's do it.
DAX:
The field's destabilizing.
We're losing power!
DAX: Temporal field
established.
We've got a DNA lock.
It's her.
( grunting )
Molly?
( snarling )
It's all right.
There's no need
to be afraid--
( yelling )
Well, there's no doubt about it.
The DNA sequences match.
This is definitely Molly.
My readings suggest
that she's 18 years old.
( groaning )
We pulled her out
10 years too late.
It's a miracle you managed
to get her back at all, Miles.
Maybe if you tried again
you could pull her out when
she was still a little girl.
If you do that,
there'll be no one to grow up
and become this Molly.
You'll be erasing
her existence.
Yes, but we'd have
our Molly back.
Miles, this is our Molly.
Just because we missed
the last ten years of her life,
doesn't give us
the right to take
those ten years
away from her.
She's been deprived
of human contact
for a long time.
It's not going to be easy
for her to reassimilate.
Her language skills
are rusty.
In fact, you two
are the best hope we have
of helping her recover them.
KEIKO:
She doesn't
remember us.
She was so scared
I doubt she even got
a good look at us.
It's possible
that she's blocked out
all memories
of her early life
in order to cope
with her isolation.
So what do we do?
Well, I'm going to keep her
under sedation
until we get back
to Deep Space Nine.
I've asked Captain Sisko
to create a safe
environment for her.
He's having one
of the cargo bays converted.
I want you two to be there
with her when she wakes up.
What happens then?
Uh, a case like this,
there are no rules.
We'll just have to feel our way
through the process.
( Yoshi murmuring )
Hi! We have
a little visitor.
Oh, come here.
And what exactly is this infant
doing in my home?
Well, I offered to watch him
so that the O'Briens could spend
some time with Molly.
I thought you said you were
going to be working tonight.
I was going to run
a spectral scan of the comet
that's passing
through the Denorios Belt
but if I did that
who'd watch you?
Me.
That's all right.
I-I want to stay with him.
Jadzia, you have been
waiting for this comet
to come into sensor range
for weeks.
( sighing )
There'll be other comets.
Go.
I will take care
of Yoshi.
Worf, that's very sweet
but... let's face it,
you're not good with babies.
I raised Alexander.
That's different.
He was four years old
when he moved in with you.
You didn't
have to change diapers.
Babies are a handful.
I should know-- I've had
nine of them.
I know-- five as a mother,
four as a father.
I can handle
a 14-month-old child.
I didn't say you can't--
Fine.
Go run your sensor scans.
Mmm...
Oh...
( crying )
You're holding him wrong.
Leave us.
All right, all right.
I'm leaving.
( crying )
Ah bom-beh mish,
Ah bom-beh mish...
( gasping )
Hello, Molly.
It's all right, Molly.
We're not going to hurt you.
Would you like
something to eat?
I bet you're hungry.
Golana melon.
Mmm...
it's delicious.
It's for you.
It's good, isn't it?
( spitting )
Hi, Molly.
Remember me?
Mommy?
( whispering ):
What is she doing?
I think she's trying
to figure out who we are.
Maybe she remembers
looking up at us
when she was little.
( murmuring )
Ma...
That's right.
Mommy...
and Daddy.
Ma.
( grunts )
( murmuring )
Show it to her.
KEIKO:
I brought you
something.
( murmuring )
It's Lupi.
She used to sleep right next to
you on your pillow every night.
She's missed you.
Go on, take her.
( chuckling )
You remember Lupi, don't you?
( sighing )
This is a ball, Molly.
May I have the ball?
Would you like
the ball, Molly?
O'BRIEN:
Molly?
Give me the ball.
Julian said
it would take a while.
Yeah, well, I hope
she catches on soon.
We're running out.
This is a ball, Molly.
Would you like the ball?
I'll give you
the ball
then you give me the ball, huh?
Give me the ball, Molly.
Molly?
Give me the ball.
Please?
Yes! That's it!
Yeah! Good girl.
O'BRIEN:
Good girl!
That's it.
That's my girl.
That's my Molly.
( Yoshi crying )
( sighing )
Is he all right?
He is fine.
He just will not
go to sleep.
Did you change him?
I changed him.
Did you feed him?
I fed him.
Did you read
him a story?
I read him a story.
Did you sing to him?
Till my throat was raw.
Oh, sounds like
you tried everything.
I'll take over from here.
That is not necessary.
Worf, you're exhausted.
Get some sleep.
No.
I am a Klingon warrior
and a Starfleet officer.
I have piloted starships
through Dominion minefields.
I have stood in battle
against Kelvans twice my size.
I courted and won the heart
of the magnificent Jadzia Dax.
If I can do these things
I can make this child
go to sleep.
Talk about losing perspective.
Listen to yourself.
Why is this baby-sitting thing
so important all of a sudden?
It is not important to me.
It is important to you.
What are you talking about?
You are judging me on my
fitness to be a parent.
Don't deny it,
Jadzia.
I can see it
in your eyes.
I have proven myself to be
a worthy husband to you
but you are not convinced
I would be a good parent
to your children.
Who said anything
about having children?
Go to sleep.
I have work to do.
( Yoshi crying )
Sorry I'm late.
( sighs )
Oh, hi.
( clears throat )
She went to sleep
a couple of hours ago.
How does she keep
from falling?
You got me.
Dax said she'd
look after Yoshi
until your shift's over.
Oh, good.
I've fallen behind
in my repair schedule
the last couple of days.
Miles.
( slight moan )
You want the brush, Molly?
You can have it.
More and more
when I look at her
I can see the little
girl she used to be.
Has she spoken yet?
No... but I can tell
she understands
what we're saying.
Has she responded
to her name?
Oh, absolutely.
Look at this.
Interesting.
She drew it.
Not bad, eh?
She's anthropomorphized
the landscape.
Yeah, she loves to draw.
Oh, did I tell you?
She began eating
with a spoon.
At this rate
she'll be reading and
writing in a few weeks.
Well, just be careful
not to push her
too hard, Miles.
If she gets frustrated,
she might withdraw
and relapse into her
old behavior patterns.
Oh, don't worry.
I'm not going
to push her.
I don't have to.
She's doing fine
on her own.
Wagh-koh
Doh-goh-ya. Gung-
gung-gung.
Gung-
gung-gung?
I was instructing your son
in Hech-doop.
Hech-doop?
It's a Klingon exercise
designed to teach children
hand-eye coordination
so they will grow up
to become warriors.
Oh, I get it--
the rattle is like
the baby's first bat'leth
kind of thing?
How'd he do?
Uh, he acquitted himself well.
Thanks for watching him.
Oh, Worf?
Um, you might want
to leave the rattle
just in case Yoshi
wants to practice
his Hech-dooping.
( rattling )
Molly, come on.
Molly...
( Molly growling )
Molly, please.
O'BRIEN:
What's going on?
She's been like this
for over an hour.
Molly...
I'll try
to calm her down.
KEIKO:
I have to go.
I have to pick up Yoshi
and take him home.
Owe-muh!
Did you hear that?
( panting ):
Hoe-muh.
Molly, what are you
trying to say?
( slowly ):
Ho-muh.
Home!
Home.
( panting )
Mol-ly.
That's right!
Molly!
Molly home.
Do you want us
to take you home
with us?
Daddy, home, Molly.
All right, we'll
take you home.
Mommy, home.
Mommy and Daddy
will take you home.
Home, Molly.
This is home.
Starry stars.
KEIKO:
They're pretty,
aren't they?
Home?
That's right.
Would you like
to see your room?
( guttural moan )
Molly... Molly.
Home!
Home.
No, this is your home.
Miles...
I know you lived
there a long time
but this is home, too.
Molly, home.
I know, sweetie.
We can't go there
right now.
( picture thuds on floor )
Maybe we can.
( giggling )
Look, Miles.
She's so happy.
( sighs )
She has no idea
it's a holosuite.
It must be
confusing to her.
One minute, she's
on a space station
the next minute, she's
running around outside.
Well, there's no reason
we can't take her here
for an hour
or two every day.
I'll talk to Quark about
scheduling some regular time.
( laughing )
Mommy... Mommy.
Daddy.
O'BRIEN: Whoa!
( squealing )
Whoa!
That's my girl!
( door chimes )
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Look at this.
Sorry to interrupt,
Chief, but, uh...
your time is up.
These gentlemen have
a reservation.
Well, I'll pay
for their time
if they can wait
another half hour.
Yaplosh daq.
They seem to have
their heart set
on some afternoon
carnage...
now.
All right.
Give me a minute.
Let me buy you
gentlemen a drink.
Oh, pretty Molly.
Molly, honey,
we've got to go.
( laughing )
Molly.
( sighs )
Computer
end program.
We'll come back
tomorrow.
( panicked groans )
Home!
We have
to go, honey.
( muttering groans )
( Molly growling )
O'BRIEN:
It's okay, it's okay.
KEIKO:
Sweetie, we'll come back
another day. I promise.
( yelling )
QUARK: I'm sorry, little lady.
( Quark yells in pain )
( Quark screaming )
O'BRIEN: Molly!
( grunting )
( yells )
( glass breaking )
( Molly grunting )
Molly!
On stun.
KEIKO: Molly?
Odo to Dr. Bashir.
We have a medical
emergency in Quark's.
SISKO:
The Tarkalean she attacked
is recovering
in the Infirmary.
Dr. Bashir tells me
he should be on his feet
in a few days.
He's filed charges
against her--
assault with
a deadly weapon.
She wasn't trying
to hurt him.
She was just trying
to get away.
I tried to
tell him that
but he wasn't interested
in hearing "excuses."
As far as he's concerned
she's dangerous
and should be incarcerated.
Incarcerated?
I've talked
to the Federation Magistrate
and explained
the situation.
She wants Molly
taken to a special care center
on Dalvos Prime for evaluation.
They're going to keep her
there, aren't they?
We might be looking
at a long-term situation, yes.
But it's the best facility
of its kind.
Molly belongs
with Keiko and me.
If she's going
to make a connection
with anybody, it's
going to be with us
not some therapist
she doesn't even know.
I'm sorry, Chief.
I wish there was another way.
Captain, please.
Don't let them
take her away.
( groaning )
Her body's flooded
with adrenaline.
I'm not sure how long
she can tolerate
being confined
like this.
It might send her
into shock.
We have to find a way
to calm her down.
( groaning continues )
Molly.
( grunts )
Daddy.
Molly, don't!
( growling )
No!
Miles!
Turn it off,
damn it!
( yelling )
Molly, Molly.
Molly.
( sighs )
What are we going to do?
It won't do any good
to keep sedating her like this.
The bottom line is
she needs open spaces
and plenty of it.
Is she going to get that
at a special care center?
I'll talk to the Captain
about putting her back
in a holosuite
for the time being.
Well, what happens
when they put her
on a transport, huh?
What happens then?
Oh, what a day.
I can't wait to get
out of my uniform.
Where's Kirayoshi?
I thought you were going
to watch him this afternoon.
Worf, what's wrong?
BASHIR:
Kirayoshi took
a little fall.
Is he all right?
Oh, yes, just a small
bump on the forehead.
Happens all the time,
children his age.
A little sleep, he'll
be as right as rain.
Thanks.
Well, I've got to get
back to the Infirmary.
You want to tell me
what happened?
We were playing.
I was pretending to be
a grint hound and chased him.
He was laughing so hard
he did not look to see
where he was going and...
fell against the edge
of the table.
It was an accident.
It could have
happened to anyone.
I was too rough
with him.
I was careless.
You were right to question
my fitness as a father.
Worf, I never questioned
your fitness as a father.
Don't put words
into my mouth.
I failed Alexander,
I failed Kirayoshi...
and I would have failed
our children as well.
Where are you going?
I should not be here
when he wakes up.
Worf...
Jadzia,
I am sorry I failed
to prove myself to you.
We've got
to do something.
We can't let them
take her away.
We don't have any choice.
We just have to hope
Molly can adjust.
How can you say that?
How can you just give up?
You're planning
something.
What are you
talking about?
Miles, I've known
you a long time.
You are planning
something
and you want to
keep me out of it.
The less you know, the better.
Why?
Because there's going
to be consequences.
So we'll face them together.
She's my daughter, too.
Keiko, listen to me.
Don't argue with me.
I am as stubborn as you.
Now, what are
we going to do?
We're going to steal a runabout
and take Molly back to Golana.
But that's the first place
they'll look for her.
They'll find her unle...
unless...
we send her back through
the portal into the past?
Yeah.
Once she's through,
we can destroy it.
That way, no one
will ever find her.
But we'll never see her again.
( sighs )
I wish there was some other way.
Golana's been her home
for ten years.
She knows how to survive there.
She'll be all right.
How is she?
Dr. Bashir said
she'd be unconscious
for a few more hours.
We'll transfer her
to a holosuite
before she wakes up.
There are
no holosuites available.
Odo said we should move her
back to the cargo bay.
He didn't mention
it to me.
Well, check the log.
He said he made
a note of it.
Did you get everything?
It's all in here.
MAN:
Chief.
Jones to Security.
I found them.
They were trying
to steal
a runabout.
ODO:
Find out if
Deputy Pinar
has regained
consciousness.
I'm going to need
his statement.
Odo, please let us go.
I-If you put her back
in a holding cell
she'll die.
I'm disappointed in you, Chief.
If anyone could break a prisoner
out of a holding cell
and get them off the station
I'd have thought it
would have been you.
On your way.
Thank you.
ODO: Go.
KEIKO:
There's a knife
and a blanket...
Ah, Lupi.
Yes, that's
right, sweetie.
( equipment powers up )
Everything's
ready to go.
I've recalibrated
the temporal
field generator.
We should be able
to put her back
at the same
moment in time
when we took her out.
Molly, honey?
Can I show you
something?
( gasps )
You're going
home now, Molly.
Home... is right
through there.
Home?
Mommy loves you,
sweetie.
I love you, too.
Go on, honey.
Home.
Stars.
Your home.
That's right.
When you look up
at the stars
that's where
we'll be...
watching you.
Go on, honey.
Molly... loves you.
( sobs )
Shh...
( sniffles )
It's okay.
( child whimpering )
Molly?
I want my mommy
and daddy.
There.
Mommy... Daddy-- there.
Molly... home.
BOTH:
Molly?
Mommy.
Oh, look at you!
Hey, sweetie.
You okay?
Hi.
You can come in.
He's gone.
I dropped him off
at the O'Briens'
a few minutes ago.
You should
have seen his face
when he saw
his sister again.
Did you apologize
to them for me?
Yes, and they said
not to worry about it.
It isn't the first time
he's bumped his head.
They invited us
to dinner tonight
to thank us for watching him.
What did you tell them?
Well, I told them
that we had
a holosuite reservation
and that I'd check with you.
By the way
what does
"gung-gung-gung" mean?
Why do you ask?
Well, it was
the strangest thing.
I was taking Yoshi home,
and he kept shaking his rattle
saying, "gung-gung-gung."
He did?
He seemed to get
a big kick out of it.
So what does it mean?
That is between Yoshi and me.
Oh, I see.
Well, you made
a big impression on him.
Maybe you're not as bad
with children as you thought.
Or as you thought.
All right, maybe
I had my doubts
but I've never been happier
to be proven wrong.
Oh, we'd better get going
if we're going to make
that holosuite
reservation.
Holosuite?
And insult
the O'Briens?
Yeah, we wouldn't
want to do that.
He really said,
"gung-gung-gung"?
Over and over again.
The Captain's volunteered
to represent me
at the hearing.
If anyone can make
Starfleet understand
what you did, it's him.
Mommy?
Yes, sweetie?
The girl who found me--
can I see her again?
Not for a while, honey.
She was so nice.
According to Dax
the recalibration
didn't hold
so the portal sent her back
to the same point in time
it sent little Molly.
I wonder if she realized
that the little girl
she was looking at was herself.
I hope so.
I hope she realized
that, in a way
she was going home, too.
Look.
It's where we had the picnic.
Don't you like it?
It's beautiful.
Aw, sweetie,
it's lovely.
Just lovely.