ODO: All right, these barstools
will have to be removed.
Do you know how much they cost?
No, and I can't say I'm interested
in learning.
Station Regulation 2562, paragraph four:
"All furniture intended
for use on the Promenade
must not pose a danger to public safety."
What danger?
ODO: Without a back on the stool
Morn could tumble from his perch
at any moment, shattering
his upper vertebrae
or puncturing three or four of his lungs.
Nonsense.
His body weight is perfectly distributed
across the seat.
He's also better able to enjoy the view
of the lovely dabo girls
than he was before
and should he require another drink
he need only spin back.
Which points out another danger...
Vertigo.
This isn't going to give anybody vertigo.
Your appeal has been heard and rejected.
I want the barstools removed
by the end of the day.
Now, it's come to my attention
that your dabo wheel is in violation
of Station Regulation 4721,
which states...
-KIRA: Odo.
-Nerys.
-You busy?
-Not at all.
Well, then can I interest you
in some lunch?
Where shall we go?
I was thinking
about the Klingon restaurant.
KIRA: I haven't been there for ages,
and I have been craving
broiled krada legs.
Too bad about the barstools.
I kind of liked them.
Did you notice how he changed
the minute she walked into the room?
-They're in love.
-And what's love?
-Well, it's a--
-Love's a distraction.
And a distracted policeman is...
An opportunity.
SISKO: Captain's Log, Stardate 51948.3.
With the safe arrival
of Convey PQ-One in the Vegan system
our escort duties are now complete
and I've set course for home.
Well, my first and hopefully
last mission report for Starfleet Command.
You know, when I first agreed
to be Convoy Liaison Officer
I thought, "Sure, why not?
I know most of the freighter captains
in the convoy.
It should be a piece of cake."
I didn't know I'd be making 20 log entries
a day and filling out
formal reports every night.
Looks like you did a pretty good job.
Well, if you're going to do something,
do it right.
That's what my father used to say.
Every father says that. Even I say that.
That's why you're a good parent.
You know all the clichés by heart.
Well, hello, stranger.
Haven't seen you in days.
I've been filling out
reports for Starfleet Medical.
I knew there was a reason
why I didn't join Starfleet.
I--I, I couldn't do this paperwork.
Smart.
Well, there was a time
when you couldn't get him to shut up.
I think I like him better this way.
-That's mean.
-I was just kidding.
No. You weren't.
Worf to Captain Sisko.
Sisko here.
WORF: Sir, can you come to the Bridge?
We have picked up a distress call.
On my way.
We have been unable
to establish two-way communication so far
WORF: but we have determined
that the signal's coming from somewhere
in the Rutharian sector.
Let's hear it, Chief.
( beeping )
( communication static )
WOMAN: and Commander Gatsby's dead, too.
I didn't see any other escape pods leave
before the ship was destroyed,
so I may be the only survivor.
My pod was torn open on impact
and the rain is pouring in.
I'll take the radio
and a survival kit with me
but the environmental suits were damaged
in the crash, so I-I'll have to rough it.
This is an L-Class world
and the atmosphere
is barely breathable out there.
Repeat, this is a general distress call.
I am a citizen
of the United Federation of Planets
and a Starfleet officer.
If you can hear me, please respond.
My government will reward you
for any assistance you can offer
and most of all,
you'll be my personal heroes. Repeat...
-That's enough.
-This is a general--
How long will it take us to reach her?
At maximum warp, six days.
Any other ships closer to that sector?
No, sir.
Mr. Worf, turn us around
and set a course for the Rutharian sector.
Aye, sir.
Chief, I want you to establish
a two-way com link with this woman
and when you do, tell her...
tell her her "heroes" are on the way.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The marooned Starfleet officer,
whose name we've learned is Lisa
continues to transmit her call for help
but so far Chief O'Brien has been unable
to establish two-way communication.
-How's it going?
-O'BRIEN: Slow.
For some reason, she's transmitting
on a rotating subspace frequency.
We're having a problem
trying to find a way to return her signal.
-Do you have to keep that on all the time?
-No, not really.
But she is all alone.
The least I can do
is try and listen to her.
She doesn't know you're listening, Miles.
You're not comforting her
by keeping the channels open
and driving yourself crazy.
It doesn't bother me.
Sometimes it feels like
she's actually talking to me.
LISA: For any assistance you can...
It's true.
Especially when she talks
about her home or her family.
She reminds me of my cousin.
LISA: Oh, no!
I don't believe it. It's raining again.
How can there be so much water
and so little life out there?
I think I'll leave you two alone.
LISA: I'm really starting
to hate this place.
Repeat, this is a general distress call.
Hello? Is anyone paying attention?
I know you're out there.
I know you can hear me.
So just answer me.
Tell me you're on your way.
Tell me I'm going to be rescued.
Tell me I'm not going to die alone.
I hope you're satisfied.
I'm sure nothing gives you more pleasure
than stifling my creativity.
( scoffs )
Only you would consider barstools
to be a form of artistic expression.
Oh, yeah? Let's see how creative you are.
Have you... picked out
the Major's gift yet?
Gift?
For this Saturday.
You do know what Saturday is, right?
-Saturday?
-Yes.
It's the one-month anniversary
of your first date with Major Kira.
-Oh... I suppose it is.
-And you haven't picked out a gift.
Why should I?
The man's experienced unrequited love
for the better part of three years
and now that he finally has her
he wants to know why
he should celebrate their anniversary.
Whatever you're trying
to sell me, it won't work.
Do you think I'm going to get involved?
No, thank you.
The last thing I want to deal with...
Is a panicked lover looking
for a gift at the last minute.
There's a whole Promenade
of shopkeepers out there
if you want to buy a gift.
Hmm. A one-month
anniversary gift. ( chuckles )
Did you ever hear
of anything so ridiculous?
-JAKE: Okay. So now you--
-Shh!
( quietly ) Now you have him
looking for a gift.
What are you up to?
I tell you, you write it down
the next thing I know,
I'm in a holding cell.
I won't write a word, I promise.
This is just character research.
-Right.
-Quark, listen.
I'm working on a crime novel
but I've hit a wall in my writing.
It's... it's not truthful anymore,
phony, artificial.
I'm having trouble creating
real flesh-and-blood characters
especially nefarious ones.
If you could just let me
watch and listen as you pull off...
whatever it is you're going to pull off,
it could really help me out.
You could give me insight.
I could even model
my lead character after you.
Lesson Number One,
No one involved in an extra-legal activity
-thinks of himself as nefarious.
-Sorry.
I'm a businessman, okay?
Now... if you're interested
in learning more about my business...
I think that could be arranged.
Great.
But nothing you see or hear
turns up in print
and none of it... none of it...
gets back to your father, understand?
Completely.
LISA: So there is a sun after all.
Of course, now that the sun is up,
I can see
how truly ugly my new little home is.
There's nothing out there
but dirt and some rocks
and some more dirt and some more rocks.
-Chief?
-Uh-huh?
-Can I ask you a personal question?
-Sure.
Are you uncomfortable
having me aboard the Defiant?
-No. Why should I be?
-Well, I'm a civilian.
Isn't it awkward having me
aboard a warship?
Oh, we've had civilians aboard before.
Doesn't bother me.
I was afraid you were going to say that.
LISA : I can hear you! I'm sorry?
Hello? Don't worry about...
O'BRIEN: Hold on a minute.
LISA: Receiving your transmission.
Can you hear me?
Hello?
( transmission clears) Hello?
I could hear you two talking.
Can you hear me?
Yes! Yes, we can hear you.
Thank God.
Whoever you are, I love you.
( laughing )
My name's Lisa Cusak.
Until a couple of days ago,
I was the commanding officer
of the Olympia.
SISKO: The Olympia?
We left the Federation
over eight years ago
for a long-range exploration
of the Beta Quadrant.
SISKO: What happened
to your ship, Captain?
LISA: We were finally heading home,
if you can believe that
but then we picked up some strange energy
readings in a nearby star system
and I decided to stop and investigate.
We found an energy barrier
around the fourth planet
that was unlike anything we'd ever seen
and when we probed it with our scanners
it triggered a quantum reaction.
There was an enormous surge
of metreon radiation
that disabled our engines.
The next thing I knew
we were spiraling in toward the surface.
I gave the order to abandon ship
and the last thing I remember
is a console exploding in my face.
I woke up in an escape pod on the surface
and I've spent the last day and a half
sitting in this cave trying
to raise someone on subspace.
Captain, Dr. Bashir,
Chief Medical Officer.
Your message said that you
were on an L-Class planet.
-Are you sure?
-Positive,
and to answer your next question
yes, I've been giving myself
15cc's of tri-ox
every four hours to compensate
for the excess carbon dioxide
in the atmosphere,
just like it says in my medical tricorder.
How much tri-ox do you have left?
One hundred and fifty milliliters.
Will you reduce the dosage, Captain
to 8cc's every six hours?
We need to stretch out
your supply as long as possible.
What happens when
she runs out of the drug?
LISA: That's a good question,
Doctor. What happens then?
You will begin to experience
the effects of hypoxia
but before that happens,
the tri-ox compound
will have strengthened
your cardiopulmonary system
allowing you to better
withstand the effects.
LISA: "Better withstand the effects."
In other words,
I'm going to be gasping for air
and turning different shades
of blue by the time you get here.
Yes, I'm afraid so.
LISA: Thanks for brightening my day.
-Is there anything we can do?
-There is, actually. I can't sleep.
I--I think the injections
are keeping me awake
and I haven't had anyone
to talk to for two days.
We'll be able to help you
with that, Captain.
I'll have one of my officers
stay on the com line
with you at all times.
And order them to enjoy it, too.
Done.
So, who's first?
I think I'd better start.
Sounds good to me.
A lot has happened...
since you left, Captain.
SISKO: The Second Fleet hit
the Dominion forces
occupying Betazed three
times in the last month
but they keep sending in reinforcements
and fortifying their positions,
so we find it--
LISA: Okay, okay...
( coughing )
That's it, please. No more war news.
You're depressing me.
Oh, sorry.
LISA: No. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for you and me
and everyone in the Federation.
I can't believe we're at war.
Let's change the subject.
How about some good news?
Tell me there's still something
to look forward to when I get home.
Tell me people still fall in love
and get married and raise families.
They do.
LISA: Good, and what about you?
Are you married?
No.
LISA: Seeing anyone?
I mean, I hate to pry
but I'd like to think
that there's still something positive
in the life of a starship captain
these days.
( sighs )
I am seeing someone.
LISA: Oh, now we're talking.
Tell me about her. What's her name?
Kasidy Yates.
Kasidy? Is she the same Kasidy
I spoke to earlier?
-That's her.
-She one of your officers?
No. Civilian. Freighter Captain.
LISA: Uh-oh. Sounds like
you're having problems.
Why would you say something like that?
There's no joy in that voice
of yours, Ben.
In fact, the tension level
went up when you said her name.
You sounded more relaxed
when you were telling me about the war.
Ben, are you still there?
( sighs ) Yes.
Yes, I'm still here. You just...
caught me off-guard... a little.
LISA: I can tell.
You know, back when I was a junior officer
I dated a civilian for six years.
( coughing ) Want to hear about it?
Sure you do.
Why? Because it's a funny story
and one of us needs to cheer up.
So, we met on Andor.
I was assigned to the Federation
Embassy as an attaché
and he was working in the Andorian
Agricultural Ministry.
Now, at first, I didn't want anything
to do with him.
He kept pointing his antennae at me
whenever I walked through his office
and I found that sort of rude.
QUARK: Excuse me... coming through.
Excuse me, excuse me...
Odo.
Well... this is it.
Can I see it?
Oh... very nice.
The Major's gonna love it.
How are you gonna give it to her?
What sort of evening do you have planned?
I don't have anything planned.
Oh... fortunately for you,
there's still time.
Pick one.
A holosuite program?
It's your anniversary.
You have to do something special.
I bought her a gift.
Have it your way. But if it were me
and I had found true love
after a lifetime of searching...
every month would be worth celebrating.
ODO: All right.
Let me look at those programs.
ODO: Come on.
Looks like the Constable's
going to be busy Saturday night.
I guess that means
he won't be following
me around the station
or watching the airlocks
for wanted criminals
or monitoring the cargo bays
for illegal transactions.
Well, he has deputies.
Deputies, I can handle.
With Odo out of the way
my biggest problem will be deciding...
what to do with all the money
I'm going to make!
LISA: Both my sisters are teachers.
I don't know how they can do it.
Personally, I can't stand children.
Uh-huh.
LISA: I know, I know,
everybody loves children.
Not me.
( distracted ) Yeah.
What about you? You like children?
Oh, yeah.
( unconvinced ) Really?
Yeah.
You know, Doctor, I'm starting to think
that maybe, just maybe
you're not really paying attention to--
Wait a minute.
What's that?
There's something moving out there.
It's getting closer.
BASHIR: What?
LISA: Stay back.
( terrified ) No. Don't hurt me.
Captain, what's going on?
( sobbing ) Please, stay back.
No, don't... ( screaming ) No!
Captain Cusak, can you hear me? Hello?
Hello? God...
DEEP VOICE: She's gone.
BASHIR: Who is this?
What have you done?
DEEP VOICE: I have eaten her.
What?
DEEP VOICE: I've eaten her!
What difference does it make to you?
You weren't even listening to her.
You have my sincere apologies.
I was carried away with my work.
LISA: I'm a patient, aren't I?
Doesn't that make me part of your work?
BASHIR: You're right,
you're absolutely right.
I don't know what I was thinking.
You now have my complete attention.
LISA: ( sighs )
Well, I've got news for you, Doc.
I'm all talked out.
It's time for you
to cheer up one of your patients
and take her mind off her impending doom.
You're not doomed.
LISA: I feel better already.
See how easy that was? Now keep going.
BASHIR: Oh, what should I talk about?
LISA: How did they let you
out of medical school
with this kind of bedside manner?
Are you sure you're a doctor?
BASHIR: Yes, I graduated
second in my class, in fact.
LISA: Oh. And we're especially
proud of that, aren't we?
I get the feeling that
it's going to take me some hours
to crawl out of this rather sizable hole
I've dug for myself.
LISA: Not at all. It'll take you days.
You have my personal assurance
they're high-quality crystals
and you won't get them at this price
anywhere else in the Quadrant.
( coughs )
( softly ) Five days,
Cargo Bay 3. See you then.
I'll take this one.
Ah... "Paris, 1928." Nice choice.
Say what you will about humans today,
their past was certainly...
( whispering ) romantic.
Well, book us four hours
starting at 2100 on Sunday night.
You mean Saturday.
I mean Sunday.
But Saturday's the anniversary
of your first date.
Yes, but our first date ended badly.
It's not something I want to commemorate
so I've decided to celebrate
the anniversary of our first kiss.
-Your first kiss?
-Romantic, isn't it? ( chuckles )
Aw...
( beeping )
Come on.
( beeping continues )
-What's going on?
-QUARK: My partner,
I can't get him on the channel.
( sighs )
-He's changed his com system protocols.
-Already? You just talked to him.
He's a wanted man, Jake.
He has to be very careful
about how often he uses subspace.
The authorities might try
and trace his signal.
( sighs )
I have no way of contacting him
until he gets here Saturday night.
Well, can't you just explain
to him that he'll have to wait
another day?
Haven't you been paying attention?
If he even sets foot on the station
while Odo's on duty,
we'll both be in a holding cell
faster than you can say
"criminal conspiracy."
( sighs )
Then, what are you going to do?
Th--think.
My best option is, uh... um...
Panic.
( sighs )
When the fighting first
broke out, I thought to myself
"All right, O'Brien,
you've done this before.
"Keep your head down...
"focus on the job
and you'll get through this,
just like you did in the last war."
But this war is different.
( chuckling ) Maybe I'm different.
I have this...
This growing sense of isolation.
I see people.
I... talk to them,
I laugh with them, and...
But some part of me is always saying...
"They may not be here tomorrow.
Don't get too close."
I'm sorry. I... I'm sorry,
I shouldn't be laying
all this on your shoulders, Captain.
LISA: No, no, it's all right,
Miles. I don't mind.
Sounds like you really need
to talk with someone about this.
I'm sure it's the last thing
you need to hear.
I should be cheering you up.
Forget about me.
You're the one who needs cheering up.
( sighs )
Now, there's a sad state of affairs.
Look, you've seen a lot
of combat in the last year.
That's a heavy burden to carry around.
Are you sure you're a Captain,
not a Counselor?
LISA: Oh, I'm sure.
I'll let you in on a little secret, Miles.
I dislike the whole concept
of a ship's counselor.
Me, too.
I mean, I--I like some of them
personally, but--
LISA: But sometimes
they just get in the way.
That's exactly how I feel,
but saying it out loud is almost heresy.
And there's this assumption
nowadays that...
only someone with a diploma
can listen to your problems
or give you advice.
LISA: Sometimes, all you need
are good friends.
Exactly.
LISA: So where are they?
What? Excuse me?
LISA: Where are your friends, Miles?
Why aren't they helping you through this?
Well, we, uh...
I haven't spoken to them
about any of this.
You know, it's not the kind
of thing you talk about.
LISA: Hmm. Well, if you can't
talk to your friends
and you can't talk to your wife,
you know who that leaves.
-A ship's counselor.
( Cusak coughing )
BASHIR: Excuse me, but it's 1800 hours.
Already?
Afraid so.
O'BRIEN: But we're still talking.
LISA: Boys, boys, don't fight over me.
( coughing ) Miles, I'll talk to you
in the morning.
And think about what I said.
All right.
And I will. Good night, Captain.
LISA: Good night.
Well, Julian, don't let me
keep you from your work.
I know how busy you are.
No work tonight.
LISA: Oh! So you've decided
to spend your valuable time
conversing with your patient again.
That's three days in a row.
You must be swamped with paperwork by now.
I feel awful, keeping you
from your duties like this.
I managed to catch up
with all my paperwork this afternoon
thank you very much.
LISA: Let me guess,
thanks to your amazing
genetically engineered brain
you not only did your work
you did the work of ten
other doctors at the same time.
Well?
But you've answered the next question
I was going to ask you,
which is "how are you feeling?"
I can hear that you're in your usual
acerbic good mood.
LISA: Wrong again, my superhuman friend.
As a matter of fact,
I'm not feeling well at all.
Tell me.
LISA: The last injection
didn't do the trick.
I feel this heavy weight on my chest.
It's getting harder to breathe
and every time I move my head,
the cave starts spinning.
( door chimes )
SISKO: Come in.
What is it?
Captain Cusak's run out of tri-ox.
She's beginning to feel
the effects of CO2 poisoning.
Already?
I thought she had at least
a day's worth of injections left.
So did I, but apparently the last vial
was tainted somehow,
probably in the crash.
-How long does she have?
-No more than two days.
That's not good.
We're still three days away.
-We need more speed.
-Speed's not the problem.
I could increase
the warp plasma 97 gigahertz.
That would increase our velocity to warp
9.5 and save us almost a full day.
WORF: The problem on the Defiant is
how to maintain structural integrity
when we go above warp nine.
Exactly. At those kind of speeds
the ship literally starts
tearing herself apart.
Is there any way to strengthen
the structural integrity field?
Not without bleeding power
from some other source.
SISKO: Such as?
-The phaser reserves.
-WORF: That would be unwise.
If we empty the defense reserves
we could find ourselves
at an extreme disadvantage
should we encounter a Dominion ship.
We're a long way from the front lines
out here, Worf.
The chances of meeting
a Dominion ship are negligible.
We should not take that risk.
She'll die if we do not get to her faster.
Use the phaser reserve, Chief.
Give us all the speed you can.
Aye, sir. Thank you, sir.
How's it going?
We're increasing speed.
The Captain's condition is worsening.
I see.
-Is there anything I can do?
-I don't think so.
Well, I guess I'll see you later.
-Right.
Are you sure you want to hear about this?
LISA: ( weakly ) Trust me, Ben.
I'd much rather be worrying
about your love life
than about my own problems right now.
( coughing )
Well, when Kasidy came
to the Bridge last night
all I wanted her to do was leave
and I couldn't tell you why.
LISA: She doesn't belong there, Ben.
That's why.
She doesn't belong in that part
of your life, and you know it.
Off duty, I'm sure Kasidy
is exactly what you need
but on the Defiant,
she's a random element...
( coughs )
a piece that doesn't fit
anywhere in the puzzle.
( sighs )
She was the Convoy Liaison
Officer on our last mission
and a damned good one, too.
LISA: This isn't about her.
This is about you.
You're having trouble doing your job
when she's on the Defiant,
and that's a problem.
It's also affecting your relationship
and that's another problem.
Don't take it so hard.
So, you can't mix your personal
life and your professional life.
Most people can't.
I certainly can't.
I once served on the same
starbase as my sister.
Oh, what a nightmare that was.
( coughs )
I look forward to meeting you, Lisa.
I'm sure I'm not the only one
around here who feels the same way.
If you ask me...
( coughs )
Everyone on that ship could use some R&amp;R.
( coughing )
Beautiful, aren't they?
Gorgeous.
Do you know how much
I was going to get for these?
Almost 200 bars.
-That's a lot.
-No kidding. That's a lot.
Now... they're just a crate full of junk.
You know, there's still a chance
that Odo won't find out about any of this.
No, he'll find out.
Odo would love nothing better
than to see me in jail.
And after all I did for him.
Like what?
Like helping him find true love.
That's right. If it wasn't for me
he and Major Kira
would never have gotten together
in the first place.
I was there for him
during all the heartache
and the lonely nights.
When he was wallowing in misery
because she was still seeing Shakaar.
I told him to make his move.
I told him not to give up.
I was there for him.
And what did I get out of it? Nothing.
He still spies on me. He still bothers me
about minor infractions of the law.
And he still can't wait
for the opportunity
to send me to prison.
I should have remembered
the 285th Rule of Acquisition.
"No good deed ever goes unpunished."
To failure.
I'm not drinking to that.
Jake, in ten minutes
my business partner's ship will dock.
In 15 minutes, Odo will arrest him.
In 20 minutes, my name will come up.
And in 25 minutes, Odo will walk
in here with a warrant.
I think you should humor me on this one.
Quark...
I'd like that holosuite now after all.
-You would.
-QUARK: That's right.
Turns out Nerys agrees with you.
She wants to celebrate the anniversary
of our first date, not our first kiss.
So here we are.
Is the holosuite still available?
It's, um... it's all yours.
The program?
Odo?
Have a good time.
Thank you, Quark.
I'm sure we will.
-I don't believe it.
-Neither do I.
I'm going to win this one, Jake.
You know what the best part is?
I beat Odo. I finally beat him.
Jake, I did it. I've beat him.
Well, he looks happy. He should be.
He's about to make
his biggest profit of the year.
I don't know, Odo.
You sure you want to let him get away
with smuggling Denevan crystals?
I owe him one.
So he'll get this one, but just this one.
Why is it every time
I think I have you figured out
you do something to surprise me?
Like tonight.
Where did you get the idea to celebrate
our one-month anniversary in Paris?
Well, some mysteries
are better left unsolved.
I want a complete scan of that barrier
but use passive sensors only, gentlemen.
An active scan is what triggered
the destruction of the Olympia.
Aye, sir.
It appears to be an exogenic field
generated by the unstable
elements in the planet's core.
Captain Cusak just lost consciousness.
She's in the last stages of CO2 poisoning.
If she's got any chance at all
we have to get her to Sick Bay
in the next 45 minutes.
O'BRIEN: Captain, there's no way
the Defiant can penetrate the barrier.
The energy's composed
of subspace metreon radiation.
If we get anywhere near it
the dilithium matrix
in the warp core will collapse
and we'll be pulled down
onto the planet's surface
just like the Olympia.
-Options?
-Could we beam through it?
No. We can't get close enough
to the barrier
to initiate transport.
What about a shuttlepod?
Their impulse engines
don't use antimatter.
It is unlikely that a shuttle
could withstand
the gravimetric stresses
that are within the barrier.
Unlikely but not impossible.
I didn't come all this way to give up.
I'll take the risk.
Doctor, Mr. O'Brien, you're with me.
Mr. Worf, you have the Bridge.
WORF: Aye, sir.
Sisko to Defiant.
We're preparing to enter the barrier.
WORF: Acknowledged. Good luck, Captain.
Thank you, Commander.
Shields down to 73 percent.
Primary power grid off-line.
Switching to backups.
Shields at 50 percent.
We're losing the navigational computer.
BASHIR: Secondary nav comp on line.
We're coming out of it.
Damage report.
Some buckling
in the starboard hull plating
but otherwise, we're fine.
Scan the planet, Doctor.
Not showing any life sign.
Wait. I found the crash site...
and the cave.
SISKO: Is there somewhere
we can set down nearby?
Yes.
-How are we for time?
-It's going to be tight.
We've got to get her in the shuttle
and back on the ship in 20 minutes.
Still no life readings.
This has to be the only direction
she could have been headed in.
BASHIR: Over here.
( tricorder beeping )
It was a human female...
Fifty one years of age at time of death.
Cause of death
carbon dioxide poisoning.
SISKO: It can't be Lisa.
That woman's been dead for years.
BASHIR: Three years and two months
but all the evidence fits.
Age, rank... the way she died.
If she's been dead for three years
how has she been talking to us?
It must have something
to do with the energy barrier.
When her subspace radio signal
passed through the metreon radiation
in the barrier, the signal somehow
time-shifted into the future.
Then when you sent the return signal?
It went through the barrier
and traveled back in time in the same way.
We've been talking
to someone from the past?
So what do we do now?
We should bury her.
No, not here. Not alone in this cave.
We'll take her back with us...
give her a proper burial...
among friends.
( muted conversation )
It's called an Irish wake.
It's a way to memorialize a death
and celebrate life at the same time.
What are we supposed to do?
Well, drink, sing songs...
Laugh, cry, talk about the deceased.
It sounds almost Klingon.
Hey.
Hey, yourself.
When this is over...
I want to talk to you about something,
something that's been on my mind.
Okay.
Um, is it about me?
Well, it--it's about me, actually.
Oh, that's a relief.
I want to try to explain
about my behavior lately.
Oh...
Sounds good to me.
But we'll talk about it over dinner.
You cook.
That's a deal.
BASHIR: I, um...
( clears throat ) I just wanted to say
that, um...
although I only talked with her
for a very short time
I really admired Lisa Cusak.
I cared about her
and I'm going to miss her.
And another thing.
Contrary to public opinion
I am not the arrogant, self-absorbed
God-like doctor that I appear
to be on occasion.
Why don't I hear anybody
objecting to that statement?
Well, I will if you insist.
-I insist.
-Then I object.
Thank you, Miles Edward O'Brien.
No, I have a heart
and I really care about all of you
even though sometimes it would appear
that I care more about my work.
To the woman who, uh, taught me
that it is sometimes necessary
to say these things,
Lisa Cusak.
-To Lisa.
I never shook her hand...
and I never saw her face...
but she, she made me laugh...
and she made me weep.
She was all by herself
and I was surrounded by my friends.
Yet I felt more alone than she did.
We've grown apart, the lot of us.
We didn't mean for it to happen
but it did.
The war changed us, pulled us apart.
Lisa Cusak was my friend...
but you are also my friends
and I want my friends in my life
because someday we're going to wake up
and we're going to find
that someone is missing from this circle
and on that day, we're going to mourn...
and we shouldn't have to mourn alone.
To Lisa and the sweet sound of her voice.