Peldor joi, Emissary.
Peldor joi to you, too.
Well, it looks like the festival
was a big success.
Oh, everyone seemed to enjoy it.
Thank you, Captain.
For what?
For insisting that the festival
take place
in spite of the fact that we're
in the middle of a war.
Well, war or no war
we have a lot to be grateful for
and we must remember that.
Yes, we must.
Shouldn't you be heading
over to the Wardroom
for the ceremony?
On my way.
Let's go.
Come on, you guys.
Mommy, look!
Isn't it pretty?
Captain.
Nerys, I've been
looking for you.
Yeah, well, I really don't feel
like talking to you right now.
Don't you want to hear
my side of the story?
No.
Well, someone has to maintain
order on the Promenade.
You arrested a vedek.
I'd hardly call it an arrest.
He wasn't in the holding
cell for more than an hour.
Besides, he broke the law.
Fund-raising on the Promenade
without a license
is strictly forbidden.
Station Regulation
1526, paragraph 7...
Vedek Solis was raising funds
for Bajoran flood victims.
A very worthy cause.
Nevertheless, station
regulations are quite clear.
I don't care about
station regulations.
Is-is-is that the Orb
of Contemplation?
Good-bye, Odo.
To Captain Benjamin
Lafayette Sisko
in recognition
of your remarkable leadership
and meritorious conduct
against the enemy
and in particular,
for personal acts of bravery
displayed during the battle
to retake Deep Space 9
Starfleet Command
is proud to present you
the Christopher Pike
Medal of Valor.
Congratulations, Ben.
Thank you, Admiral.
And to think I knew him
when he was just a callow youth.
Oh, I bet even then,
he showed signs of greatness.
I'm proud of you, Dad.
Now if you would all excuse us
I'd like a few words
with the Captain.
Good news, Ben.
Starfleet Command has decided
we've been waging
a defensive war long enough.
They figure we're never
going to win this thing
unless we take the fight
into Dominion territory.
No, I know, I know
you've been saying that
since the Romulans opened a
second front with the Dominion.
Well, it took a while
but your message
finally got through.
Well, when do we go?
That all depends on you.
Me?
That's right, Ben.
Starfleet has chosen you
to plan the invasion
of Cardassia.
Oh, finally.
I've been waiting
20 minutes for you two
to get out of that holosuite.
I'm sorry, Julian.
We lost track of time.
Doing what?
You were supposed to be up there
exercising.
I don't see any sweat.
Where are all the bruises?
The-the, the broken bones
- the blood?
- We were talking.
For an hour and 45 minutes?
It is a private matter.
We're thinking
about having a baby.
It was a private matter.
Kira to Worf.
Report to Ops immediately.
Acknowledged.
Well, you two are awfully quiet.
Uh, look, um, I-I-I don't want
to dampen your spirits, Jadzia
but I told you
before you were married
that from a medical
point of view
it wouldn't be easy for a Trill
and a Klingon to have a child.
And I'm worried
the kid'll end up
looking like his father.
Well, I hope she does.
A baby?
It's bad enough she married
that Klingon psychopath.
A baby?
Do you have any idea
what that means?
That their marriage
is going to last
a lot longer than we thought.
Five squadrons
of Jem'Hadar attack ships.
At the moment, that's
the entire Dominion fleet
protecting the Chin'toka system.
Only five squadrons.
It appears you've
found the weak spot
we've been looking for.
Now, all we have to do
is to convince
the Romulans to join us.
That will not be an easy task.
They're an arrogant
and untrustworthy people.
Without their help, we have
little chance of success.
We will succeed!
Mark my words.
By this time next year
the three of us
will drink bloodwine
in the halls of Cardassia's
Central Command.
You're worrying over nothing.
Am I?
It's a mistake to underestimate
our enemy, Damar.
You're spreading
our forces too thinly.
Until we find a way
to bring reinforcements
from the Gamma Quadrant
we have to make do
with what we have.
Besides, we needed new ships
on the Romulan front,
so I sent them.
And in doing so
you left the Chin'toka
system vulnerable.
Not as vulnerable as you think.
We don't need starships
to protect Chin'toka.
Not anymore.
These are our new, unmanned,
orbital weapon platforms.
Their hulls are protected
by regenerative
force fields,
and their arsenals consist
of a thousand plasma torpedoes.
I like them.
I thought you would.
I've already ordered
their deployment.
Legate Damar,
excuse the interruption
but we have a problem.
What kind of a problem?
Me.
Well, isn't anyone
going to welcome me home?
Heroes get welcomed home, Dukat,
not failures
or have you forgotten
that under your leadership
the Dominion
nearly lost this war?
As I recall, Weyoun
you were standing
right by my side
agreeing with every decision
I made.
If you're here because of what
happened to your daughter...
Damar...
you disappoint me.
I would have thought you,
of all people
would be glad
to see your old mentor.
I don't hold you responsible
for Ziyal's death.
You may have fired the phaser
but it was Benjamin Sisko
who forced your hand
and that's why I'm here.
The time has come
for me to take my revenge
against the good Captain.
We're in the middle
of a life-and-death struggle
for the control
of the entire Alpha Quadrant
and all you care about
is quenching your petty thirst
for revenge.
You haven't changed
a bit, have you?
On the contrary, I'm a new man.
I no longer have a need
for conquest or power.
I'm far beyond all that.
I exist in a state
of complete clarity...
a clarity I intend to share
with the universe.
You're right, Dukat,
you have changed.
You've gone from being
a self-important egotist
to a self-deluded madman.
I hardly call that
an improvement.
I don't have time for this.
Remove him.
Wait.
Why did you come?
Isn't that obvious?
To give you what you desire
above all else...
the Alpha Quadrant.
All I need
is a certain Bajoran artifact...
one of the many
the Cardassians appropriated
during the occupation.
And how is this artifact
going to help us?
Let's just say,
it will make it possible
for Dominion reinforcements
to come through that wormhole
and destroy
Captain Benjamin Sisko
and the Federation,
once and for all.
Really, Captain
I see no reason
why I should sit here
and allow this Klingon jackal
to call me a coward.
Apparently, this "jackal"
has more courage
than the entire Romulan Senate.
There, you see my point?
General, you must
try to remain calm.
This is not the time for calm.
It's time to strike the enemy
and strike them hard!
We have found
their weak point.
Now we need to exploit it.
But this p'tagh
would rather sit home
and count his dead.
If we invade Cardassia now
all we'll do is count our dead.
Gentlemen, please.
We're allies, remember that.
What good is an ally
who'll stab you in the back?
Notice the primitive rage
in his eye
the uncontrolled brutality?
Klingons can be quite
entertaining, can't they?
Every Romulan zoo
should have a pair.
Sit down, General!
Save your anger
for the Dominion.
Senator...
you've studied
our invasion plans.
Yes, I have
and I continue
to find them premature.
Let the Dominion continue
to send its fleets against us
and we will annihilate them
one by one.
And they'll continue
to rebuild their ships
and send more.
The Dominion breed Jem'Hadar
faster than we can destroy them.
The only way to achieve
a lasting victory
is to demolish their shipyards
their weapons plants
to force them to retreat
deeper and deeper
into their own territory
until our ships
can surround their headquarters
on Cardassia Prime
and they will have no choice
but to surrender.
I know it won't be easy.
I know that we will pay
a heavy price
for every system
we take from them
but in the end
that's the only way
to drive the Dominion
out of the Alpha Quadrant
and that is the goal
we all share!
Klingons, humans...
and Romulans.
Here's to those
who love not wisely
No, not wisely, but too well
To the girl who sighs with envy
When she hears
that wedding bell
To the guy who'd throw a party
If he knew someone to call
Here's to the losers
Bless them all
Hey, Tom, Dick and Harry
Come in out of the rain
Those torches you carry
Must be drowned in champagne
Here's the last toast
of the evening
Here's to those
who still believe
All the losers will be winners
All the givers shall receive
Here's to trouble-free tomorrows
May your sorrows all be small
Here's to the losers
Here's
to the losers
Here's to the losers
Bless them all.
That was great, Vic.
It's not one of the most
requested songs
in my repertoire,
but I'm glad you liked it.
So, why the long face, pally?
Ah, it's a long story, friend.
This wouldn't be
about Dax's baby, would it?
What is he, a telepath?
No, I'm a hologram.
A very smart one.
It's simple.
You take one beautiful,
happily married filly
add the possibility
of her giving birth to a foal
and what's it leave you?
Couple of lovesick stallions
that never got out
of the starting gate.
You have any idea
what he's talking about?
Hey, I got news for you guys.
It's time to move on
to greener pastures.
It's tough to lose
a woman like Dax.
I hate to break it to you, pally
but you lost her
a long time ago.
You both did.
But lucky for you, space is big.
There are a lot of other
nice girls out there...
with or without spots, capisce?
That's it?
That's supposed to cheer us up?
"The truth shall set you free."
You feel any better?
A little.
How about you?
I guess.
Good, 'cause you were starting
to depress the band.
Well, thanks, Vic.
We appreciate the advice.
I like this place.
I may drop by more often.
Anytime, pally, anytime.
Nice guys...
but absolutely clueless.
So, when do we leave?
We?
I'm a journalist, Dad, remember?
Well, that may be true,
but you're not going, Jake.
But, Dad, we're talking about
the invasion of Cardassia...
a savage thrust
into the very heart
of the Dominion.
Well, I mean, that's not
how I would write it.
That's a relief,
but you're still not going, son.
I have to go.
It's my job.
Now, if you don't want
me on the Defiant, fine.
I'll go with General Martok.
Hey, get the story
from a Klingon perspective.
All right, Jake,
the Defiant it is.
So, when do we leave?
Just keep your bags packed.
Yes, sir.
Don't worry, Dad.
We'll watch out for each other.
The Sisko is of Bajor.
It is where he belongs.
It is where he is meant to be.
Are you telling me
not to go to Cardassia?
The Sisko is of Bajor.
It is dangerous
to walk a different path.
Dangerous? In what way?
The Sisko must not leave
the chosen path.
The Sisko is of Bajor.
It is where he belongs.
Why is it dangerous to leave?
And how will it affect Bajor?
You have to tell me.
The Cardassians call them
orbital weapon platforms.
Intelligence reports indicate
the Dominion has
placed hundreds of them
throughout
the Chin'toka system.
Are they operational?
- No, not yet.
- How much time
do we have before they are?
Two, maybe three days.
So, it would appear
that your weak spot
is about to become
much stronger.
Leave it to a Romulan
to run at the first sign
of trouble.
And leave it
to a Klingon to leap
to the wrong conclusion.
The Romulan Empire
has agreed to join
the invasion of Cardassia
and we live up
to our agreements.
The only question is:
Can the invasion
be launched before
the defensive grid is activated?
We'll have to leave
first thing in the morning.
Then it's settled.
Good luck, gentlemen.
Good luck to all of us.
Romulans don't believe in luck.
All the better!
It leaves more
for the rest of us.
You've been, uh, quiet, Ben.
Those weapon platforms
have you worried?
It's not about that, sir.
It's about the Prophets.
The wormhole aliens...
they spoke to me last night.
I hope they gave
the mission their blessing.
They told me
not to go to Cardassia.
That I should stay here.
Did they give you a reason?
Nothing concrete.
Just that it's too dangerous.
In what way?
Dangerous to you?
To the mission?
To Bajor?
I'm not sure.
What is it you're telling me,
Ben?
You want permission
to stay behind?
It's not about what I want.
It's about what the Prophets
want.
That's not
a good enough answer...
not from a Starfleet Captain.
The Prophets don't see me
as a Starfleet Captain.
They see me as their Emissary.
That's the problem, isn't it?
For the past six years,
you've tried to be both
and up to now,
I've been patient.
I've indulged you.
I've gone out on a limb for you
many times, but this is it.
You've got to make a decision.
You are either the Emissary
or a Starfleet Captain.
You can't be both.
I'll...
I'll be on the Defiant Bridge
at 0500.
The combined fleet
at Deep Space 9?
Composed of Federation,
Klingon and Romulan ships.
You think they'll head
for the Chin'toka system?
I would.
Well, then,
we have nothing to worry about.
The weapon platforms
will be operational
in time to greet them.
That's a very comforting thought
if it's accurate.
I'll make sure that it is.
Gentlemen, I hope
I'm not interrupting.
What is it now, Dukat?
I've found it.
Behold...
the key to victory.
Oh, I see you remain skeptical.
Well, you won't be for long.
Over the past few months,
I've immersed myself
in the study
of the Bajoran ancient texts
and I've come to realize
that the wormhole
is much more than the gateway
to the Gamma Quadrant.
It's the Temple of the Prophets.
It's from there
that they smile
benevolently down on Bajor.
It's from there
that they protect that world
and its people.
The sad truth is
we wasted our time
fighting the Bajorans
when we should have been
fighting their gods.
How do you fight a god?
I'll show you.
You see...
we have an ally
we never knew we had.
You may want to step back.
Dorrah
tolka betri...
pah'rahn
meedor.
Dorrah tolka... ullkess
pah'rahn!
Dukat!
Your concern is touching...
but unnecessary.
Busy?
Uh... a little.
Well, I'm leaving
with the task force
first thing in the morning.
I heard.
And?
And...
I'm sorry I arrested him.
I was simply
trying to do my duty,
but I can see
how it might have
seemed excessive.
What are you talking about?
Vedek Solis.
That's why you're here,
isn't it?
No...
but now I know
why you've been avoiding me
for the past few days.
I haven't been avoiding you.
I've been helping you
to avoid me.
Why would I want to do that?
Because... you don't want us
to be together anymore?
Is that what you've
been thinking?
Odo, we had an argument.
People have them all the time.
Look at Dax and Worf.
They love each other,
but they fight all the time.
Are you saying that you love me?
Don't change the subject.
Which is?
I don't even know anymore.
But you're no longer angry
with me?
No, but you were wrong
to arrest the vedek.
- I see.
- And I thought
that we could spend my last
night on the station together.
That's a wonderful idea.
Then I will see you later.
I look forward to that.
Good.
You know, Nerys...
observing humanoid relationships
and being in one...
are very different things.
Like night and day.
If you ask me, it's an
ungodly hour to go to war.
You can quote me on that.
I will.
Oh, Jadzia, will you look in
on Keiko and the kids
while I'm gone?
You can count on it.
And try to keep
Julian out of trouble.
Now, that's pushing.
It's your station, old man.
I'll take good care of her.
Give my best to the Jem'Hadar.
Oh, I'll do that.
I said a prayer
at the shrine last night
for the two of you.
About having a baby?
The Prophets can be helpful
in such matters.
I hope they're listening.
Did you hear that?
We have the Prophets
on our side.
According to Dr. Bashir,
we need all the help we can get.
Just remember when you get back
we have a lot of work to do.
I don't consider that work.
Wish I was going with you.
You are...
in here.
I love it
when you get romantic.
Captain on the Bridge!
As you were.
You got here early.
This is a momentous occasion.
It's not every day
I embark on a journey
to liberate my homeworld.
That's one way to put it.
This is General Martok
to all ships.
Assume tactical formation.
We are moving out.
Take us to Cardassia, Mr. Nog.
Aye, sir.
The enemy fleet is approaching
the Chin'toka system.
What's the status
of our weapon platforms?
Still off line.
It pains me to say this
but you Cardassians are proving
to be quite a disappointment.
I'll remind you
that you said that.
Looks like we're in luck,
Captain.
The defensive grid's
still off line.
Jem'Hadar fighters approaching.
Bearing 059 mark 031.
They must know
they don't stand a chance
against a fleet this size.
That will not matter
to the Jem'Hadar.
Sit down, Jake.
Right.
Martok to Sisko.
Go ahead.
My attack wing is closest
to those Jem'Hadar fighters.
Preparing to engage.
Good luck, General.
I always thought
the Jem'Hadar were crazy.
There's method to their madness.
They're inflicting considerable
damage on the Klingons.
And buying time to get their
weapon platforms operational.
Sisko to Martok.
The Jem'Hadar have managed
to cripple or destroy
15 of my ships.
Do you need any assistance?
That won't be necessary.
Commence firing
on the weapon platforms.
I believe you owe me an apology.
I believe you're right.
Now, if Dukat can get
our reinforcements
through the wormhole...
I'm not sure how much faith
I have in this...
What did he call it?
Pah-wraith.
Pah-wraiths and Prophets?
All this talk of god strikes me
as nothing more
than superstitious nonsense.
You believe that the Founders
are gods, don't you?
That's different.
In what way?
The Founders are Gods.
We are unable to penetrate
their force fields.
Captain
I've just noted something odd
about those platforms.
Well, don't keep it to yourself,
Mr. Garak.
Not one of them seems to have
a power generator on board.
He's right.
Each one seems to be
getting its power
from a central source.
We got to find that source
and destroy it.
Chief?
I'm on it.
According to the DNA
scans I did this morning
the ovarian resequencing
enzymes I gave you
appear to be working.
You mean, Worf and I
can have a baby?
It certainly looks that way.
I must say, I didn't expect
such positive results so early.
It's quite amazing, actually.
Oh, thank you, Julian!
It's all part of being a doctor.
Oh, no, it's more than that.
You're a good friend...
you always have been.
And I always will be.
I'd better get back to work.
But first I'm going to stop by
the Bajoran shrine.
What for?
Kira said a prayer
for me and Worf last night.
She told the Prophets how much
we wanted a baby.
Well, I'd say
they've been listening.
That is, if you believe
in the Prophets.
Oh, well, I do today.
I'm not sure
if I'm doing this correctly.
I... I don't come here a lot.
And to be perfectly honest
I feel more comfortable thinking
of you as wormhole aliens
but, um...
Kira believes
you're much more than that.
Maybe she's right.
I don't know.
But if you are Prophets
and you're listening
I just want to say...
Dukat.
Dad, what is it?
Captain!
I'm not sure.
I think I felt the Prophets
reaching out to me.
Something's wrong.
Sir, I found it.
There's a subspace power
generator on a small moon
orbiting the far planet.
It's transmitting energy
to the weapon platforms.
Captain?
Take us there, Mr. Nog.
Aye, sir.
Get him back to his quarters.
Don't worry, Captain.
We'll get the job done.
I know this is small comfort
but I never intended you
any harm.
Approaching the target.
Onscreen.
Target locked.
Fire.
We are unable to penetrate
the moon's defensive grid.
Sir, I have an idea.
Go ahead.
Maybe we can't destroy
that power generator
but I bet
those weapon platforms could.
Why would they fire
on their own power source?
We'd have to fool the platform's
targeting systems
into thinking
the generator's an enemy ship.
We can use our deflector array
to imprint a Federation
warp signature on the
generator's energy matrix.
It is worth a try.
Evasive maneuvers, Mr. Nog.
Pattern theta.
Induction stabilizers set.
Booster modulators synchronized.
Ready to activate deflector.
Do it.
Yes!
We did it.
Martok to Defiant.
Go ahead, General.
Well done, Major.
We will begin
transporting ground troops
to both planets immediately.
Major, we're receiving
a priority one
transmission from Deep Space 9.
It's from Julian.
This is a disaster.
Federation soldiers
have landed on Cardassian soil
and now you're telling me
the wormhole is gone?
And with it, any chance
of getting reinforcements
from the Gamma Quadrant.
I'm well aware
things didn't turn out
quite the way I planned
but I assure you, we still
achieved a great victory.
Forgive me if I don't
share your euphoria.
Well, you should.
The Bajoran people have been
cut off from their Gods
perhaps forever.
How does that help us?
Because Sisko has been cut off
from the Prophets as well
and without the Prophets
he's just another
Starfleet Captain.
And that's supposed
to make me feel better?
Oh...
believe me... it will.
Emissary, Emissary.
Emissary!
My mother says
all the Orbs are dark
that the Prophets
have abandoned us.
You have to find them, Emissary.
You have to ask them
to come back.
I will try.
I managed to save
the Dax symbiont.
We have to get it to Trill
as soon as possible.
There was, um...
nothing I could do for Jadzia.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Save your strength.
Our baby...
would have been so beautiful.
NeH taH Qo'noS.
Hegh bat'lhqu Hoch nej maH.
Yay je bat'lh manob Hegh.
The funeral service is due to
begin in a few minutes, Jadzia
but I need to talk to you
one last time.
When I first met you
you told me that my relationship
with Jadzia Dax
wouldn't be any different
than the one I had
with Curzon Dax.
Things didn't work out that way.
I had a hell of a lot of fun
with both of you.
But Curzon was my mentor.
You... you were my friend
and I am going to miss you.
I should've listened
to the Prophets
and not gone to Cardassia.
Then maybe you'd still be alive.
Damn it!
Why aren't you still here,
Jadzia?
I need you to help me
sort things out.
Something's happened
to the Prophets...
something that's made them
turn their backs on Bajor
and I'm responsible
and I don't know
what to do about it
how to make... it right again.
I've failed as the Emissary...
and for the first time
in my life
I've failed in my duty
as a Starfleet officer.
I need time to think...
clear my head...
but I can't do it here
not on the station
not now.
I need to get away.
And find a way to figure out
how to make things right again.
And I have to make things
right again, Jadzia.
I have to.
The station's all yours, Major.
She'll be here
when you get back.
This leave of absence
you're taking, sir
how long do you think
you'll be gone?
I don't know exactly.
We'll be waiting.
Good luck, sir.
Thanks, Chief.
My thanks to all of you.
Let's go home, Jake.
Landing Pad C.
I was afraid of that.
He's not sure he's coming back.
What makes you say that?
His baseball...
he took it with him.
Dad...
Grandpa's ready to close
up the restaurant.
He wants to know when
you're coming in.
In a little while.