Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
Starfleet has chosen you
to plan the invasion
of Cardassia.
( grunts )
( gasping )
I managed to save
the Dax symbiont.
There was...
nothing I could
do for Jadzia.
( roaring )
Federation soldiers
have landed on Cardassian soil
and now you're telling me
the wormhole is gone?
And with it, any chance
of getting reinforcements
from the Gamma Quadrant.
Why aren't you still here,
Jadzia?
I need you to help me
sort things out.
Something's happened
to the Prophets...
something that's made them
turn their backs on Bajor
and I'm responsible
and I don't know
what to do about it,
how to make... it right again.
I've failed as the Emissary...
and for the first time
in my life,
I've failed in my duty
as a Starfleet officer.
The station's
all yours, Major.
She'll be here
when you get back.
Let's go home, Jake.
And now, the continuation.
( chanting )
ODO:
Colonel.
KIRA:
I wish you'd stop
doing that.
Doing what?
Calling me
by my rank.
I was promoted
two months ago.
Besides, it sounds
so formal.
Well, has Admiral Ross--
or should I say "Bill"--
arrived yet?
The Admiral's ship
is due in three hours
and I wish I knew
what he wanted
to talk to me about.
Maybe he's bringing
good news.
We could
certainly use it.
Yeah, well, don't get
your hopes up.
There was something about
the tone of his voice.
Something ominous?
Something pleasant.
It was like he was going
out of his way to be nice.
I see.
Well, whatever he wants
to tell me,
he knows I'm not
going to like it.
And how can you
be so sure?
( sighs ):
It comes with the job.
Uh-huh.
No, I'm serious.
Sitting in
the Captain's chair,
having that kind
of responsibility--
it focuses you.
Well, I'll take
your word for it.
( Bajoran chanting continues)
How long have
they been there?
Three days.
I remember
when the cult
of the Pah-wraiths
used to be a joke.
Now those red armbands are
appearing all over Bajor.
It's like everyone's
gone crazy.
A lot of people feel
abandoned by the Prophets.
Believe me, I know
how they feel.
It's no excuse
to turn to hate and fear.
In times of trouble,
some people find comfort
in hate and fear.
If you like, I can charge
them with loitering
and have them removed
from the station.
Ah, what good
would that do?
I keep thinking if the
Emissary were here...
things might be different.
I would've thought
we would've heard
from Captain Sisko by now.
Not a word in
three months.
Nerys...
I realize that things
may seem
bleak at the moment,
but there's always hope.
When did you turn
into an optimist?
Must've been that day
in front of Quark's
when we kissed
for the first time.
Hmm.
That was some
kiss, wasn't it?
Changed my life.
Gentlemen... we are home.
Oh, there should be a law
against convoy duty
lasting more than ten days.
I'll say one thing
for guarding convoys--
it's usually a lot safer than
being on the front lines.
Is that the reason you joined
Starfleet, Ensign--
to be safe?
I... I didn't mean that
the way it sounded, sir.
In wartime, it is the duty
of every soldier to fight.
Yes, sir.
The invasion of Cardassia
has ground to a halt
while our casualties
continue to mount.
It is a time for warriors
to do great deeds,
to triumph in glorious battles
not waste away protecting
a shipment of stem bolts.
I hope Commander
Worf doesn't think
I'm afraid to fight.
Relax. Don't take it
so personally.
Worf is just going through
a bad time at the moment.
I think he needs to focus on
something other than Jadzia
and I hate to admit it,
but a little combat duty
might just do the trick.
Pretty soon the Defiant
will be going into battle.
Worf will be happy
and the rest of us
will be miserable.
It's not that
I'm afraid to fight.
I just don't want to die.
( sighs )
I wish Captain Sisko
were here.
So do I, Ensign.
So do I.
JOSEPH:
If I were you,
I'd order
the crawfish étouffée.
And if it's good enough for you,
it's good enough for him.
( chuckles )
I think table five
is ready to order.
He's been at that piano
since 7:00 this morning.
The customers
seem to like it.
Grandpa...
Look, I'm worried, too.
But he's got something
to work out.
Best we leave
him alone.
We've left him alone
for the past three months.
He said he came here
to figure out a way
to contact the Prophets,
to make things right.
So far, he hasn't even left
the restaurant.
( breathing heavily )
( heartbeat thumping )
( wind whistling )
( heartbeat continues )
Dad...
what's wrong?
Dad?
I had a vision
from the Prophets.
I was on Tyree
in the desert...
digging in the sand.
And I uncovered a face...
the face of a woman.
And?
And that's all.
Who was she?
I've never seen her before.
But now I know why
I came back here, Jake.
I have to find her.
I have to.
ROSS:
Colonel, I really don't see
anything for you
to be concerned about.
I've met Senator Cretak
and found her to be...
very cooperative.
For a Romulan.
Cretak's a strong supporter
of the Alliance
and we're going to need
that kind of support
if we're going to win this war.
I wouldn't care
if the Romulans
were the only thing
standing between us
and total annihilation.
I would still think twice
before allowing
them to establish
a military presence
here on the station.
We're just talking
about a few officers
for the Senator and her staff.
And a contingent
of personal guards--
A dozen people
at most.
Besides, it's just
a temporary arrangement
until the end of the war.
And when will that be?
Let's get one thing straight,
Colonel.
I came here
as a courtesy to you.
This decision
has already been made.
And I have to live with it.
That's right.
You've done a fine job
taking over for Captain Sisko.
I'm just keeping
his seat warm.
You still think
he's coming back?
Don't you?
I'll be in touch.
As you can see, we've halted
the Klingon advance
against Monac IV.
We estimate their casualties
to be at least 30 percent.
They should've been higher.
Nevertheless,
congratulations, Damar.
The enemy remains bottled up
in the Chin'toka system
and that's where they'll stay
until we destroy them.
I'd offer you a glass
but I know how much
you dislike kanar.
I'm beginning to think
you like it too much.
I wouldn't trust a Cardassian
that didn't enjoy a glass
of kanar every once in a while.
Tell me, Damar,
when you're alone,
do you even bother
with a glass
or do you just drink that swill
directly from the bottle?
Depends on my mood,
and right now,
I feel like celebrating.
We owe Gul Dukat
a debt of gratitude.
Unfortunately, I agree.
Somehow, releasing that
Pah-wraith into the wormhole
has shifted the momentum
of the war into our favor.
You ever wonder
what goes on?
Inside the wormhole,
I mean?
Not really.
The Prophets and
the Pah-wraiths
locked in some form
of... celestial battle.
It's fascinating.
I never realized you had
such a vivid imagination.
There's a lot about
me you don't know.
Just remember--
too much imagination
can be... dangerous.
( padd beeping )
Dad, Grandpa and I
are going to Armstrong Park
to listen to some music.
You want to come?
You two go ahead.
( sighs )
Who's that?
The woman in my vision.
I don't want to forget her face.
I'll see you
in the morning.
Hey, I-I've seen her before.
Where?
In a photograph.
Yeah, I'll be
right back.
( sighs )
Here she is.
I knew it.
That's her, isn't it?
SISKO:
She's with Grandpa.
I don't understand.
Who is she?
Why don't you ask Grandpa?
Ask me what?
This woman.
Where'd you get this?
I found it last week
when I was cleaning out
the storage room.
I-I meant to ask you about it.
So, who is she, Dad?
No one at all.
You hear me?
She's no one at all.
Hey, pally, where you
been keeping yourself?
Convoy duty.
Doesn't sound
very exciting.
It was not.
Well, if you're looking
for some action,
you've come to
the right place.
What do you say we hit
the crap tables, huh?
Or maybe some blackjack
to get the blood pumping?
Sing the song.
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
Sing the song.
Come on, pally, why rub
salt in an open wound?
You are a hologram.
You are programmed
to do as I say.
Sing the song.
It's your dime.
Park it right there.
And don't say I didn't warn you.
Which reminds me of a story
Joey once told me--
Sing!
Son of a gun,
I think he means it.
Hey, you heard the man.
( soft ballad intro )
♪ When somebody loves you ♪
♪ It's no good
unless he loves you ♪
♪ All the way ♪
♪ Happy to be near you ♪
♪ When you need someone
to cheer you ♪
♪ All the way ♪
♪ Taller
than the tallest tree is ♪
♪ That's how it's got to feel ♪
♪ Deeper
than the deep blue sea is ♪
♪ That's how deep it goes
if it's real ♪
♪ When somebody needs you ♪
♪ It's no good
unless he needs you ♪
♪ All the way ♪
♪ Through the good
or lean years ♪
♪ And through all
the in-between years ♪
♪ Come what may ♪
♪ For who knows
where the road will lead us? ♪
♪ Only a fool would say ♪
♪ But if you let me love you ♪
♪ It's for sure
I'm gonna love you ♪
♪ All the way... ♪
( roaring )
( clattering, glass shattering)
( Worf roaring )
This monitor is
still off line.
I want it operational
within the hour.
I hope all the chairs
on this station
aren't this uncomfortable.
KIRA:
I'm afraid
they are.
But don't worry,
you'll get used to them.
I'm sure I will.
You must be Colonel Kira.
I'm sorry I wasn't
at the airlock
to greet you
when you arrived, but I was--
No need to explain,
Colonel.
You must be quite busy.
I hope you find your
accommodations satisfactory
other than the chairs,
of course.
I'm sure we'll be
quite comfortable here.
I trust that won't be
a problem for you.
Meaning what?
My people have
a reputation for arrogance.
I'm afraid it's well-earned.
But you're different.
Or so Admiral Ross tells me.
The Admiral and I have
a good working relationship.
I hope to have
a similar one with you.
I'd like nothing more.
Then I look forward
to working with you
toward our common goal--
the destruction of the Dominion.
BASHIR:
Worf did this?
VIC:
With his own two hands.
And it's not the first time
he's busted up the joint.
I don't care
how much he threatens me,
that's the last time
I ever sing "All the Way."
If he wants to hear it again,
let him buy a Sinatra album.
"All the Way"?
That was Jadzia's favorite song.
I'm sorry, Vic,
but you're going
to have to forgive him.
He's having a hard time
accepting her death.
So am I, but you don't see me
busting up the joint.
She wasn't
your wife.
She should have been.
There is
something wrong.
That's what I've
been telling you.
Klingons usually have
a shorter mourning
period than humans.
They accept death
more readily than we do.
Well, something
is driving Worf cuckoo.
Your buddy needs
some serious help
and soon.
The band is
threatening to quit.
QUARK:
They can't quit.
They're holograms.
They don't know that.
I'll see
what I can do.
Hang in there, pally.
I'll try, but I think
Jadzia's death
has made us all
a little cuckoo.
Dad?
You should be in bed.
Not until you tell me
what I need to know.
I already told you.
She's no one.
You're going to have
to do better than that.
Leave it be, Ben.
I can't.
I saw her.
The vision
the Prophets sent me--
she was the woman
in the desert.
That's impossible.
I'm telling you, I saw her.
You couldn't have.
Dad, please, who is she?
I'm sorry, but I don't
want to talk about it.
Dad...
No.
You have to tell me!
I need to know who she is!
Her name was Sarah.
I met her
in June of '31.
It was in Jackson Square.
She was, without a doubt,
the most beautiful woman
I'd ever seen.
Two months later...
we were married.
Married?
You had a wife before Mama?
It's a little bit more
complicated than that, Ben.
You see...
Sarah was your mother.
Sarah and I were married
for two years.
She seemed very happy.
I certainly was.
Two days after
your first birthday
she disappeared.
What do you mean,
she disappeared?
She left me.
Why?
I've asked myself that
question a thousand times.
I never did come
up with the answer.
And you never found out
what happened to her?
It took me
three years
but I found out.
She was living
in Australia
working as a
holo-photographer.
Well, I have to speak with her.
You can't.
Damn it, Dad, I have to.
She's dead.
She died in
a hovercraft
accident
about a month before
I tracked her down.
I loved that woman...
and-and she loved me.
I-I know she did.
Why didn't you tell me
about her?
I wanted to, many times,
but you were so young
when she left.
I grew up.
I thought that might
make it easier, but it didn't.
That's no excuse.
I know.
I-I'm sorry, but you see,
you and your stepmother
were so close.
She... made
you laugh
like nobody else,
and I didn't want anything
to get in the way of that.
I loved Mama.
Nothing would've changed that.
She said the same thing.
You should've listened to her.
Life is full of choices.
You make them and
hope for the best.
Sometimes you're right, and...
sometimes you're not.
I made a mistake.
Yeah...
you did.
I-I... I still don't understand
why the Prophets would send you
a vision of Sarah.
I came back here
to clear my head,
to try to figure out
what to do next.
Maybe learning the truth
about my mother
is the first step
of this journey.
Well, from here on out,
I hope the Prophets keep
their noses out of my business.
Are there any other secrets
I should know about?
Just my gumbo recipe,
but I'm taking that to my grave.
( chuckles dryly )
Colonel...
I was just coming
to see you.
What is it?
Nothing. I...
I just never thought I'd see
a Romulan eating a jumjastick.
I was... curious.
And?
It has a...
distinct flavor.
Personally, I can't
stand them-- too sweet.
Then you should try
a Romulan osol
twist-- very tart.
I'll do that.
I wanted to let you know
that a squadron of warbirds
will be arriving
at the station
tomorrow morning
for refitting.
I'll tell Chief O'Brien
to start replicating
Romulan system modules.
Excellent.
I had no idea Bajorans
were so efficient.
Coming from a Romulan,
that's quite a compliment.
Oh, one more thing.
It's about Bajor's
fourth moon.
Derna.
It's uninhabited, correct?
Last time I checked.
Do you think
your government
would allow us
to set up a hospital
facility there?
Too many of our
wounded are dying
on the long journey
back to Romulus.
I'll ask
the Council of Ministers.
I'd appreciate anything
you can do.
You've got to get him talking
but whatever you do,
don't mention Jadzia.
Let him do that.
I don't think Worf
wants to talk about her.
Well, he may not want to,
but he needs to, I think,
and given the right
circumstances, he will.
Well, we have one circumstance
in our favor.
2301-- a very good year
for bloodwine.
I'll let you
do your work.
You sure one bottle's
going to be enough?
Good-bye, Julian.
Chief.
Can I come in?
Why?
Well, because it's
been a long time
since we shared
one of these.
Got any glasses?
None that are clean.
Well, who needs
glasses, eh?
Cheers.
Mmm.
Warm the cockles.
Very smooth.
Good night, Chief.
Well, hold on. You
call that a visit?
I enjoyed it.
Come on, Worf.
I came to talk.
About what?
Anything you want.
Old friends,
the Enterprise...
Remember what's
his name?
Ah, eh, Lieutenant
Barclay?
Who can forget him?
( laughing )
Those holosuite
programs of his, huh?
Three Musketeers.
Yeah-- Geordi waving
that sword around.
( laughing )
Oh...
That's better.
So, what did
you find out?
That you should never try
to match drinks with a Klingon.
Yeah, yeah, but what did
you and Worf talk about?
What do you care?
Because some day
that crazy Klingon
may get tired of smashing
up a holosuite bar
and decide to come down here
and smash up a real one.
What did you talk about?
A lot of things.
His son, Alexander...
growing up in Russia...
the proper way to eat gagh.
But what does any of that
have to do with Jadzia?
Nothing.
It wasn't until
about 0400
when we were polishing off
the third bottle of bloodwine
that he even
mentioned Jadzia.
You know, this could
be a little sweeter.
Miles, what did he say
about her?
She's not in Sto-Vo-Kor.
You mean Klingon heaven?
What would she
be doing there?
She wasn't a Klingon.
As far as Worf is concerned,
she was.
Well, she did join
the House of Martok.
Then what makes him think
she's not in Sto-Vo-Kor?
Well, for one thing,
she never ate the heart
of one of her enemies.
She always was
a little squeamish.
And secondly, she didn't die
in glorious battle.
You mean being murdered
by a Pah-wraith
in cold blood
doesn't count?
Do you want to know
what's bothering Worf or not?
There's more?
Well, apparently there is a way
for Worf to ensure that Jadzia
gets into Sto-Vo-Kor.
He has to win
a great battle in her name.
Well, I could let him
beat me at tongo.
Not good enough.
Unless he has
to carve his way
through a hundred Jem'Hadar
to get to the table.
Why does everything
with Klingons
have to involve
bloodshed?
No wonder he's so frustrated
with convoy duty.
Maybe we should talk
to Admiral Ross.
Oh, yeah, I can see it now.
"Admiral, could you please
send the Defiant
"on the most dangerous mission
you can think of?
Jadzia needs to get
into Sto-Vo-Kor."
Sounds good to me.
Then you ask him.
What about General Martok?
He's due to arrive
on the station tomorrow morning.
Good thinking.
Who better than a Klingon
to help a Klingon?
It's a beautiful night,
isn't it?
I'm sure you're right.
You thinking
about Sarah?
Actually, I was
thinking about Jadzia.
She always used to be here
to help me sort things out.
I miss her.
I know you do.
I came out
to give you this.
It was Sarah's.
I want you to have it.
I think she
would've, too.
Thanks, Dad.
There's some kind
of writing on the back.
What's the matter?
This writing...
it's... ancient Bajoran.
What does
it say?
I don't know,
but I intend to find out.
I still don't understand
why Sarah would have a locket
with Bajoran writing on it.
I don't recall her ever
mentioning Bajor to me.
Maybe she didn't
know it was Bajoran.
Maybe it was a gift
or something.
Finally! Some progress.
JOSEPH:
What is it?
The inscription-- it says,
"Orb of the Emissary."
I never knew there was
an Orb of the Emissary.
I've never heard
of it, either.
At least, there's
no mention of it
in the ancient
Bajoran texts.
Sounds like you've
reached a dead end.
Not necessarily.
What if the Orb
does exist?
What if it didn't go dark
like all the others
when the wormhole
disappeared?
If you can find it,
maybe you can find a way
to contact the Prophets.
Oh, I'm going to find it.
But it could be anywhere.
Where do you begin
to look?
Tyree.
Why there?
Because that's
where I was
in the vision
the Prophets sent me.
CRETAK:
Are these the latest
casualty reports?
From the Dominion
counterattack
in the Chin'toka system.
I'm afraid that
your people took
the brunt of the assault.
What matters is that
we held our position.
As for our casualties,
at least we now have
the hospital complex on Derna
to care for the wounded
and we have you
to thank, Colonel.
Oh no, all I did was
put in your request
to the Council
of Ministers.
They made the decision.
Under your advisement,
I'm sure.
All of Romulus owes you
a debt of gratitude.
I'll keep that in mind.
Do you have a moment?
I do for you.
This morning,
a Starfleet transport
filled with wounded
was denied permission
to dock at the Romulan
hospital complex on Derna.
Well, the hospital
may not be equipped
to treat other species.
I thought the same
thing myself
until I noticed that most
of the wounded were Vulcans.
Vulcans and Romulans
share a common physiology.
And a mutual distrust
of one another.
That doesn't change
just because they're allies
against the Dominion.
True, but how do you explain
these sensor readings?
High concentrations
of trilithium isotopes.
Which indicates the presence
of Romulan plasma torpedoes.
I'll look into it.
( grunting )
Defend yourself, Worf!
So, how do you
like convoy duty?
I don't.
Good. I was afraid you
might be getting soft.
( growling )
I need a First Officer
for a dangerous mission.
How dangerous?
Dangerous enough to assure
Jadzia a place in Sto-Vo-Kor.
In that case, you have found
your First Officer.
Excellent.
It will be
a great victory.
I will make sure of it.
( laughing )
How many clams you
think you've cleaned
since we got here?
A lot. That was going
to be my last batch,
but then I got
to thinking.
Maybe I'll take a couple
of sacks along with me
tomorrow on the runabout.
Give me something to do
on the way to Tyree.
You're kidding, right?
Jake...
if I never see
another clam...
It'll be too soon.
...it'll be too soon.
( both laughing )
Whoo!
( whistling )
Can I help you?
Emissary, I've come
a long way to see you.
This moment is sacred,
one that will be
long remembered.
Meeh rak Dorah Pah-wran.
Ee-toi Velah-slah.
Pah-wran amar...
Pah-wran Evak-too.
That's ancient Bajoran.
The Emissary is wise.
Well, thank you, but, uh...
right now, the Emissary
has to get back to work.
Your work is finished.
The Orb you are seeking--
the Orb
of the Emissary?
What did you say?
( gasps, bowl clatters )
You're never going to find it.
( grunts )
Grandpa! Grandpa!
Today's special
is shrimp creole.
Uh, actually,
it's barbecued shrimp.
( door opens )
Excuse me.
Where were you?
They told me
you were released
from the hospital
two hours ago.
SISKO:
I had to give a report
to Starfleet Security.
And the Bajoran
that attacked you--
who was he?
He was a member of a cult
that worships the Pah-wraith.
They believe that the
disappearance of the Prophets
will herald
a new era for Bajor.
I don't suppose I can talk
you out of going to Tyree?
If you're worried
about the cult--
I figure you can
handle them.
But if the cult knows
you're looking for
the Orb of the Emissary
chances are the
Pah-wraiths do as well
and that does worry me.
Well, here's to Worf
and the success
of his mission.
Qapla'.
I don't see why
the two of you are so happy.
An entire Klingon fleet
failed to destroy
the Dominion shipyards
on Monac IV.
What makes you think one
ship will do any better?
The element of surprise.
If you ask me, it's not
a mission-- it's suicide.
You're beginning
to depress me, Quark.
Why? You're not going.
You can't be serious.
I've never been
more serious in my life.
I'm going to help Jadzia
get into Sto-Vo-Kor.
What makes you think she wants
to spend eternity there?
I know I certainly wouldn't.
Imagine what it must be like!
Hordes of rampaging Klingons
fighting and singing,
sweating
and belching.
Sounds like this place
on a Saturday night.
Would you want
to spend eternity here?
You know, that's a good point.
What if Jadzia would prefer
to go to, you know,
wherever it is that Trills go
when their time is up?
Miles, you don't understand.
You weren't as close to her
as I was.
This gives me a chance
to honor her memory
and I'm going to take it
and that, my friend,
is my final word on the subject.
Well, you know
what this means, don't you?
Yes-- that I am risking my life
for a very dubious cause.
No.
It means, I'm going
to risk my life for a friend
who's risking his life
in a very dubious cause.
You're going with him?
Well, somebody has to make sure
he comes back in one piece.
Miles, I don't know what to say.
I'm touched.
You're both touched.
You want to get Jadzia
into Sto-Vo-Kor?
Fine, fine, I'm all for it.
But can't you do something
more sensible?
Make a donation in her name,
or bribe someone.
It doesn't work that way, Quark.
Be nice if it did.
Third Fleet has requested
two more attack wings
of Romulan warbirds.
That shouldn't
be a problem.
Now, if we--
Senator, I have
a message for you
from the Bajoran
Council of Ministers.
We're in the
middle of a meeting--
Sorry, sir.
This can't wait.
Apparently, we are no
longer welcome on Derna.
They want to close
down the hospital?
No, the hospital
isn't the problem.
Then what is?
The 7,000
plasma torpedoes
the Romulans have
secretly deployed there.
Is this true, Senator?
The weapons are for
defensive purposes only.
Well, my government
doesn't agree.
You're to begin
an immediate evacuation.
I'm afraid
that's impossible.
Let's try to stay calm.
I'm sure we can reach
some sort of compromise.
Not this time, Admiral.
My government considers
a Romulan presence on Derna
to be a direct
threat to Bajor.
This is ridiculous.
I regret
not informing
your government
about our weapon emplacements,
but I didn't think
it was necessary.
We're your ally.
Then remove the weapons.
That would leave
the hospital unprotected.
Bajor will guarantee
its safety.
I'm afraid that's
not acceptable.
Either you remove
those weapons, or we will.
( door opens, closes )
See that Gul Yaltar
of the Third Order
receives this immediately.
Have you heard?
The Romulans have
taken over a Bajoran moon
and heavily fortified it.
My guess is that
the Bajorans aren't
happy about that.
Would you be?
This is the sort
of unfortunate situation
that could destroy
an alliance.
That would be a pity.
Romulans-- they're so
predictably treacherous.
What's going on?
Why is
the restaurant closed?
I am going on
vacation to Tyree.
We're coming
with you, Dad.
Have you both
lost your minds?
Apparently, it runs
in the family.
Well, you've obviously
already packed your bags.
Yes, and I even brought
my toothbrush.
( knock at door )
Oh, nothing I hate more
than turning away a customer.
I'm sorry. We're closed.
That's all right,
Mr. Sisko.
I'm not hungry.
I'm here to see Ben.
Well, you're in luck.
Five more minutes
and he'd have been gone.
Hello, Benjamin.
Do I know you?
It's me... Dax.