Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space 9...
I managed to save
the Dax symbiont.
There was...
nothing I could do for Jadzia.
Federation soldiers
have landed on Cardassian soil
and now you're telling me
the wormhole is gone?
And with it, any chance
of getting reinforcements
from the Gamma Quadrant.
The station's all yours, Major.
Let's go home, Jake.
I need a First Officer
for a dangerous mission.
How dangerous?
Dangerous enough to assure
Jadzia a place in Sto-Vo-Kor.
I had a vision
from the Prophets.
I was on Tyree in the desert
and I uncovered a face...
the face of a woman.
You had a wife before mama?
Sarah was your mother.
You're to begin
an immediate evacuation.
I'm afraid that's impossible.
Either you remove
those weapons, or we will.
Hello, Benjamin.
Do I know you?
It's me... Dax.
And now, the continuation.
Dax.
I can't believe it.
I can hardly believe it myself,
but I'm Dax.
I mean, I'm not Jadzia Dax.
I'm Ezri Dax.
But I have
all of Jadzia's memories...
not to mention Lela's,
Tobin's, Emony's, Audrid's
Joran's, Curzon's.
Am I forgetting anyone?
Torias?
Right, you're probably
asking yourself,
"Who is this person?"
"How did she get the symbiont?"
"Do I even want another Dax
in my life?"
"Does she always talk
this much?"
These are all
very good questions.
And I wish I had good answers
for you.
The answers can wait.
Right now, I'm just
glad to see you.
Really?
That is so nice of you to say.
I'm not usually this emotional.
It must be the Emony in me.
At least, I think it's Emony.
Hi, Jake.
Hi.
You seem taller.
Or am I shorter?
Oh... You know, none
of this was my idea.
I never wanted to be joined.
Then how did you get
the symbiont?
It was an accident.
Some accident.
I was on the Destiny
when they brought
the Dax symbiont aboard
to be taken back to Trill.
Halfway through the trip
the symbiont took
a turn for the worse
and it needed to be placed
in a host immediately...
And you were
the only Trill onboard.
I laid down on that
operating table one person
and I woke up
a completely different person.
Well, I should say
eight different people.
I was not prepared for this
at all.
I mean, you're supposed
to get years of training
and preparation
before you get joined
and all I got was
a 15-minute lecture
from the ship's surgeon,
and he wasn't even a Trill...
I'm starting to see the problem.
Please.
You don't know
how much better I feel
just being here with you, Ben.
What about
the Symbiosis Institute?
Weren't they able
to do anything for you?
I did meet with the Evaluation
Board several times.
And?
They gave me some books to read,
some counseling
but once a host
and symbiont are joined
there's really not very much
they can do.
My parents, my friends,
my crewmates...
it's like they don't
even know me anymore
which is understandable
since I hardly even know myself.
That's why I took
a leave of absence to come here.
I knew that if there was anyone
who could help me through this
it would be you.
I'll do all I can
but the truth is...
we're leaving for Tyree.
Fine.
I'll come with you.
Uh, you don't even
know why we're going.
It doesn't matter.
When do we leave?
Today.
Great.
It'll be just like old times...
except different.
Jadzia Dax Vond Shoo-vwee Dun
maHh-kekh Huh-Qoo-vaHm
jeh yin-moj maH-mukh.
Sto-Vo-Kor paH-dahkh-tin
baht'leH
el-eegh-cha yay-moj.
Quark, son of Keldar.
Did I come at a bad time?
What's he doing here?
Same thing you are.
I'm volunteering
for this mission.
Why?
You're a bartender,
not a warrior.
True. But I loved Jadzia
as much as anyone
in this room...
with maybe one or two exceptions
and I am willing
to pledge my life
to see that she gets
into Sto-Vo-Kor.
Perhaps there is some
Klingon in you after all.
I wouldn't go that far.
So, uh, why all the cutlery?
We shed our blood to prove
we are not frightened of death.
Can't you just take
my word for it?
Ow! That hurts.
It's supposed to hurt.
Oh!
YuWee-modge.
Baht'leH-modge.
Yay-dodge.
This is so embarrassing.
Well, don't worry.
It's not your fault.
I am a trained
Starfleet Officer.
I have no business
getting spacesick.
But ever since I was
given the symbiont
warp speed does make
me a little queasy.
A little queasy?
Well, the main thing is
the control panel's
all cleaned up.
So if one of you'd
like to get back
into the pilot's seat
it would sure make me
feel better...
not that I don't trust
the computer.
You just prefer the human touch.
Do you need to lie down?
No. I'm fine, really.
Hmm. Well...
it's time for my nap.
You sure you're okay?
Mm-hmm, but I just wish
I could stop thinking
about Torias.
Torias Dax?
He was one of the previous
hosts, wasn't he?
He died in the shuttle accident.
I still remember
the last few seconds
before the crash.
Maybe I don't belong
in Starfleet anymore.
Aren't you glad
you brought me along?
Actually, I am.
My dad seems a lot happier
ever since you showed up.
One iced raktajino.
I know you've been worried
about your father, Jake
but he's going to be all right.
What makes you so sure?
Because I've known
him for a long time.
Besides, it's my job
to know these things.
I'm a Ship's Counselor.
Well, actually,
an Assistant Ship's Counselor.
You're a therapist?
Is it that surprising?
A little.
You know, I wasn't
always this confused.
Before I was joined
I was considered to be
a very promising young officer.
Oh, that is horrible.
I hate raktajino.
Then why'd you order it?
Because Curzon liked it.
Hmm. So did Jadzia.
Well, I don't.
I have to learn to control
some of these urges.
Oh.
Uh...
I want you to know, Colonel
that I'm as outraged as you are.
The Romulans have no business
placing weapons on Derna.
I'm glad we're in agreement.
What are we going
to do about it?
The Federation has already sent
a formal protest
to the Romulan Senate
condemning their actions.
Well, that's a start.
What happens next?
Well, they've already sent
a protest of our protest.
Politics.
Well, you still haven't
answered my question.
I don't know, Colonel.
Eventually, the Romulans
will remove the weapons.
When?
Are we talking about days,
weeks, months?
I don't know,
but it will happen.
Now you sound
like a politician, Admiral.
Maybe so, but facts are facts,
Colonel, and there's no way
the Bajorans can drive
the Romulans off Derna...
not without help, anyway
and the Federation isn't going
to provide that help, not now.
Is that clear?
We're just not as important
to the war effort
as the Romulans.
That's a harsh way to put it.
The truth often is.
Colonel, I would
like to help you
but my hands are tied.
Well, luckily, mine aren't.
Meaning what?
Our scans show
that the weapons aren't
fully operational yet.
They're still missing
launch sequencers.
I'm going to make sure
that those sequencers
never reach Derna.
How?
I'm going to set up a blockade.
If you do that, Colonel
you'll have a fight
on your hands...
a fight you can't win.
We're entering orbit.
Prepare to beam down.
Why don't we use the ship's
scanners to find the Orb?
There's too much ionization
in the atmosphere.
It'll interfere
with our sensors.
You sure you don't want
to stay here and wait for us?
And miss all the excitement?
Not a chance.
Well, be sure you're carrying
plenty of water packs.
That goes for both of you, too.
It's dry down there.
Dr. Wykoff, please report
to Isolation Ward 4.
Dr. Wykoff, please
report to Isolation Ward 4.
Did you hear that?
Hear what?
Forget it.
If there is an Orb buried
around here
my tricorder's
not picking it up.
I know it's out there someplace.
That's why the Prophets
sent me here.
Did they give you any hint
which way to go?
That way.
The Prophets have spoken.
I hope he heard them right.
Once we're close enough
we can fire an EM
pulse at the sun.
The sun?
I thought we were trying
to destroy a shipyard.
We are.
Do you understand
what he's talking about?
Always.
Fine. Then you explain it.
We are going to fly toward
the molten heart of the sun
so close that our ship will glow
like a flaming comet.
Well, hopefully not that close.
Just close enough to trigger
a solar plasma ejection.
The explosion should be enough
to incinerate everything
within a hundred
million kilometers.
Including the shipyard.
It will be a glorious firestorm
that will illuminate
the gates of Sto-Vo-Kor
itself, and provide
a fitting welcome for Jadzia.
The things we do for love.
Did you see that?
See what?
The way he glared at me.
He always glares at you.
Well, I'm sick of it.
We're risking our lives
to help Jadzia
get into Sto-Vo-Kor.
The very least Worf could do
is show us some appreciation.
Is it so hard to say thank you?
Thank you.
Nice try, Doctor
but I want to hear it from him.
Don't do this, Quark.
Do what?
All I'm asking for
is two little words.
Be quiet!
That's two words, all right
just not the two
I was hoping for.
Why should I feel
any gratitude towards you?
I owe you nothing.
You are not here
to help Jadzia
get into Sto-Vo-Kor.
You are here because you wish
to convince yourselves
that you are worthy of her
but the truth is, none of you
could ever hope
to be worthy of her
or even understand
the kind of woman she was.
It is you who should be
thanking me, Ferengi
for allowing you
to come on this mission
and pay honor to her memory.
Think we're getting close?
I have no idea.
But we're headed
in the right direction?
I hope so.
Audrid loved to walk.
Of course, she
preferred the woods...
nice shady glens, cool
breezes, cold streams.
Dax, what are you trying to say?
You've been keeping
a pretty fast pace.
It might be a good idea
to give your father and Jake
a chance to rest.
If anyone wants to take a break
they can go back
to the runabout.
I think we should
stick together.
Hey, Dad!
How you doing back there?
Never better.
It's only a matter of time
until we break through
enemy lines
and when that happens
we can drive
the Federation-Romulan alliance
out of Cardassian territory.
A bit more kanar?
Please.
To victory...
on all fronts.
Damar, have you...
Weyoun.
This is Siana.
We met at the dinner last night
honoring Legate Hovas.
Damar, you and I have things
to discuss...
things that your guest
doesn't want to hear.
And why is that?
Because if she does, I'll be
forced to have her executed.
I really should be going.
Until tonight.
What a pleasant woman.
Now.
It's imperative
we increase production
at the Monac shipyard.
We need more assault ships
to retake
the Chin'toka system.
Damar
are you listening to me?
Increase production.
Yes, I heard you.
By how much?
15 percent would be ideal.
That won't be easy.
Oh, I'm sure you'll find a way.
You're very resourceful.
A blockade?
How many ships are
we talking about?
12 impulse ships.
It's all the Council
of Ministers
could spare right now.
And how effective do you think
those 12 ships are going to be
against even one
Romulan warbird?
You sound like Admiral Ross.
Well, I was hoping
that our relationship
was going to be
a long and happy one
but I suppose
I'm willing to settle
for short and exciting.
What's that supposed to mean?
I take it you're going to be
commanding the blockade?
That's right.
Then I'm going
to be there with you.
You don't have to do that.
Yes, I do.
Well, I wouldn't start writing
our epitaphs just yet.
All right, I'll wait until
the first wave of Romulan ships
decide to run the blockade.
Don't worry.
I have no intention
of getting into a firefight
with a squadron
of Romulan warbirds.
You mean you're bluffing?
If the Romulans fire on us
they jeopardize their alliance
with the Federation
and I'm hoping
that that's a risk
they don't want to take.
And I'm hoping they
don't call your bluff.
Grandpa, you sure
you don't want to go
back up to the runabout?
We started this together
and we'll finish it together.
I owe it to Ben.
I got you.
Let's go.
Doctor Wykoff, please come to
Isolation Ward 4 immediately...
to Isolation Ward 4,
Doctor Wykoff.
Doctor Wykoff, please come
to Isolation Ward 4
immediately.
Benjamin.
Benjamin, is this it?
I think so.
You're not sure?
Ben, that's not good enough.
Ben.
Are you listening to me?
There.
Where?
That's where
we start digging.
Why there?
I wasn't even
aiming at anything.
Ben, maybe my memories
are playing tricks on me
but have you gotten stranger?
Ship's Log, Stardate 52152.6.
We've set up a blockade
around Derna.
So far, no Romulan ships
have tried to challenge it.
"Kiss Me Deadly."
Interesting title.
Mmm. The book isn't bad, either.
I think you'll enjoy it.
I'm sure I will,
but is this really
the right time
to start reading a book?
Well, maybe not,
but I know how much
you hate all this waiting
and Mike Hammer
has certain qualities
I think you'll appreciate.
Hmm...
such as?
He's as tough as they come
and he hates waiting
almost as much as you do.
Oh, I like him already.
Hmm...
Colonel, there's a priority one
transmission from Deep Space 9.
It's Admiral Ross.
Put him through.
Colonel, Senator Cretak
has just informed me
that 14 Romulan warbirds
are on their way to Derna.
They'll be arriving
in eight hours
with much-needed
medical supplies
for the hospital complex.
Since when did the Romulans
start using warbirds
to deliver medical supplies?
We want to make sure
they arrive safely.
Well, if they try
to get through the blockade
they're not going
to make it at all.
That kind of talk isn't going
to help matters, Colonel.
I'd think you'd want
to avoid a confrontation,
not provoke one.
Well, I wouldn't call
those Romulan ships
a peace offering.
Well, I wasn't exactly happy
to hear about that, either...
but we only have a few hours
to reach some sort
of compromise.
After that, people are
going to start dying.
Well, you can talk about
compromise all you want.
Any ship attempting to
break through that blockade
will be fired upon.
Colonel
do you seriously believe
that your antiquated
collection of impulse ships
stands a chance
against our warbirds?
We'll find out soon
enough, won't we?
End transmission.
How'd I do?
Mike Hammer
would have been proud.
You're concerned.
Aren't you?
Not really.
The Colonel is a brave woman,
but she's not stupid.
She's bluffing.
Right over there.
Shade.
Here.
Oh.
There you go, Grandpa.
Dr. Wykoff, please come
to Isolation Ward 4.
Dr. Wykoff
I wish he'd get there.
Who?
Dr. Wykoff.
They're waiting for him
in the Isolation Ward.
You have definitely
gotten stranger.
What about me, Worf?
Would you rather I hadn't
come on this mission, either?
That is not what I am saying.
With you, it is different.
You are a Klingon and Jadzia
was a member of your House.
And these men were her friends.
They honor her
with their presence.
I don't believe it...
gagh for breakfast
gagh for lunch,
gagh for dinner...
Am I the only one who thinks
Klingon menus need
to have more variety?
You want to complain
about their gagh
that's fine with me
but don't complain about it
when we're in the mess hall
sitting at a table surrounded
by a dozen Klingons.
All right, all right,
I get the point.
Good.
But I'm telling you
I think some of those Klingons
agreed with me.
Look, uh, Worf,
if this has anything to do
with what just happened
in the mess hall...
No. No, it does not.
What's the matter?
Come up with a few more insults
to throw at us?
I wish to apologize.
I'm listening.
I know Jadzia meant
a great deal to all of you
and you meant
a great deal to her.
Many times, when we
discussed our day
she would repeat
something amusing
that you had told her
or describe, in endless details
the intricacies
of some new scheme of yours.
She often talked
about all of you.
It seemed as though,
even when we were alone
one of you was always with us.
I get it.
You were jealous
because she liked us
better than you.
Quark, would you please
keep quiet.
She was my wife, my par'machkai.
I did not like having
to share her affections.
Oh, that's
why you didn't want us
on this mission with you.
You wanted to get her
into Sto-Vo-Kor
without our help.
I wanted it
to be my gift to her.
Go on.
There is nothing more to say.
Except that I am
pleased you're here.
I have never heard Worf
apologize to anyone.
I don't know about you,
but I was hoping for something
a little more... intriguing.
Such as?
You know, like... Jadzia used
to call my name out
when she slept, or...
wanted to name
her first child after me.
Chief...
the Monac shipyard.
Impressive.
Display our target.
How close do we have
to get to that?
Too close.
Perfect.
What is it, Dad?
Have you found something?
Stay back.
The Orb of the Emissary.
What are you going to do?
Open it.
Mr. Russell...
Mr. Russell, put it down.
Benjamin
what's wrong?
Benjamin.
I said put down the pencil.
Put it down, Mr. Russell.
But I-I haven't finished
my story yet.
Captain Sisko has found
the Orb of the Emissary...
but he hasn't opened it yet.
Mr. Russell, you promised
not to write on the walls.
No one will give me any paper.
I thought we agreed
that you weren't going
to write at all...
that you needed to rest.
No, I don't need to rest.
I need to tell my stories.
You were doing so well, Benny...
making real progress.
We were all so proud of you.
I-I need to go home.
I don't belong here.
And we're going to send you
home, as soon as you're well.
I'm fine.
But you're not fine.
People who are fine
don't write on walls.
Then get me a typewriter.
You're not listening.
The stories have
got to stop, Benny.
They are too dangerous.
But too dangerous to whom?
To you.
This world you've created,
this... Deep Space 9
Captain Sisko and Kira
and the others...
none of it is real.
Oh, it is to me.
If I don't...
finish my story...
if... if Captain Sisko
doesn't open the Orb box
then he cannot contact
the Prophets.
It doesn't matter, Benny.
The Prophets don't exist.
They're all figments
of your imagination.
Get rid of them.
It's the only way
that you're going to get well.
Now, give me the pencil, Benny.
But my story...
It's over.
Just let it go.
Benjamin
what are you waiting for?
Open it.
That's why we're here, right?
He can't hear you.
Jake!
Jake... are you all right?
Yeah.
Ship's Log, supplemental.
Senator Cretak said
that the Romulan warbirds
would be here in eight hours.
She was wrong.
They're two hours early.
They'll be in weapons
range in eight minutes.
Open a channel.
Go ahead.
This is Colonel Kira
of the Bajoran Militia.
Any ship traveling within
transporter range of Derna
will be considered hostile
and fired upon.
They're not responding.
Kira to all Bajoran ships.
Prepare to engage.
Sir, Admiral Ross
is asking to speak to you.
Put him through.
Colonel, I'm appealing to you
one last time
to end this blockade.
Well, you know
I can't do that, Admiral.
Be aware
that I'm authorized to use
whatever force is necessary
to see that our medical supplies
reach their destination.
However, I'm also
authorized to seek
a negotiated settlement.
My government has made
its position quite clear.
There are to be no negotiations
as long as there are
Romulan weapons on Derna.
Damn it, Colonel.
If you open fire on those
ships, we all lose.
The only way
to beat the Dominion
is to keep our alliance intact.
Besides... I would hate to see
you throw your life away.
Your concern is touching,
Senator...
but I'm not dead yet.
End transmission.
At least not for
another six minutes.
You still think she's
going to back down?
She has to...
because I won't.
Take me out of the oven, Moogie.
I'm cooked.
General, I found it...
a magnetic instability
near the sun's equator.
Excellent.
Now, let's trigger
that solar ejection
and get out of here.
I'm afraid it's not that simple.
We have to make sure
the ejection has
the right trajectory
to destroy the shipyard.
Well, how do we do that?!
We have to get closer...
much closer.
He's right.
Sto-Vo-Kor...
here we come.
Take it, Benny.
What for?
I'm offering you an opportunity
few people ever get.
You can wipe away
all your mistakes.
You want me
to paint over my story?
They're only words.
Meaningless words
that no one cares about.
Get rid of them
and you can walk out
of here a free man.
Go ahead.
Save yourself.
Ben?
I've got to cover it up;
bury it.
Ben, what are you doing?
It's for your own good, Benny.
Wipe away the words.
Destroy them before
they destroy you.
Ben, stop!
The Romulans have
powered their weapons.
I think they're
calling your bluff.
Auxiliary power
to forward shields.
Kira to all ships.
Hold your positions.
Nerys, if you're going to end
this, I suggest you do it now.
Time to fold, Colonel.
Oh, damn it.
We're ready, General.
De-cloak and prepare to fire...
on Worf's command.
Fire!
It didn't work.
Oh, well, we tried.
Time to go.
No! Not until we complete
our mission.
We'll have to increase
the magnetic gradient.
I'll recalibrate the deflector.
We might not have time.
There are three Jem'Hadar ships
approaching.
Bearing 005 mark 190.
I suggest
you work quickly, Chief.
No!
Get out of my way.
Ben, you came here to find
the Prophets, remember?
Move!
No, listen to me!
You promised Jadzia
you would make things right.
Well, now is your chance.
Open the box, Ben.
No!
Colonel...
do we stand down?
Sir, we're getting
a transmission
from Deep Space 9.
The wormhole... it's back.
On screen.
Nerys?
Open a channel
to all Bajoran ships.
Hold your positions
and prepare to fire
on my command.
Lock targets.
Targets locked.
Still glad you came along?
I wouldn't have missed it
for anything.
I'm afraid the Colonel
has run out of time.
Well, Worf, did I not promise
you a glorious battle?
It is everything I hoped for.
EM pulse ready, General.
What are you waiting for?
Fire!
By all means, Chief, fire!
It's working!
Great. Now, can we leave?
Full impulse.
Qapla'!
I hope Jadzia
appreciates all this.
I'm sure she does.
Lohm-Ict'liHj...
posh-machh-Lodge
Sto-Vo-Kor...
Jadzia Dax...
pay-Lodge pah-doQ-lih Dun.
Shoo-vweee-vahm
baht'leH pay-Lodge.
Pay-Lodge poh'hoqH-vahd
Sto-Vo-Kor.
Nerys, they're pulling back.
Colonel, Admiral Ross
would like to speak with you.
Put him through.
You can blink now, Colonel.
You've won.
Senator Cretak has agreed
to remove the weapons
from Derna.
What changed her mind?
I told her, if she didn't
remove them, I would.
Then what changed your mind?
You did.
Remind me never to play poker
with you.
Show yourselves.
I've come to speak with you.
The Sisko
has completed his task.
Sarah?
The Kosst Amojan
no longer threatens us.
You mean the Pah-wraith?
It's no longer in the wormhole?
I have cast it out.
Is that why the Prophets
sent me to Tyree...
to release you from the Orb?
The Kosst Amojan tried
to stop you with a false vision
but you did not waver.
You fulfilled your destiny.
My destiny?
You talk as if my life was over.
The Sisko
must still face many tasks.
I don't suppose
you'll tell me what they are.
The Emissary is corporeal...
linear.
Linear or not,
I need some answers.
The Sisko is intrusive.
Are you Sarah Sisko?
Are you my mother?
Sarah Sisko was corporeal.
For a time,
I shared her existence.
You took over her body...
made sure
she married my father...
so that she'd give birth to me.
The Sisko is necessary.
And once you didn't need
her anymore, you left her.
No wonder she walked
out on my father.
She didn't choose him, you did.
The Sisko would prefer
different answers.
What you're telling me
isn't easy to accept.
You arranged my birth.
I exist because of you?
The Sisko's path
is a difficult one.
But why me?!
Why did it have to be me?
Because it could be no one else.
Benjamin?
That must have been
some Orb experience.
I'll tell you about it someday.
Bravo.
Emissary, welcome.
Welcome back, Captain.
We missed you, sir.
Thank you for bringing
the Prophets back to us.
I heard you've all been
pretty busy yourselves.
Odo! Nerys, Julian,
it's so good to see you.
Worf, we need to talk.
Who's that?
That's Dax.
Dax?
That's right. Ezri Dax.
Incredible, isn't it?
It cannot be.
She's so much... shorter.
Just when you thought
things couldn't get
more interesting.