It's funny...
before yesterday,
I'd never set foot
on this station, but...
it's as familiar to me
as the back of my hand.
Isn't that odd?
You have no idea
who I am, do you?
I didn't think so.
Thanks for
listening, anyway.
( sighs )
I was killed here.
I mean, Jadzia was.
I try not to think about that.
If I did, I'm not sure
that I could come back here.
It's a strange sensation--
dying.
No matter how
many times it
happens to you,
you never get used to it.
It must be
a little disconcerting for you
knowing that I have
Jadzia's memories.
No wonder you're uncomfortable.
It's a lot to get used to.
Tell me about it.
Well...
I'll let you get
to your prayers.
Bloodwine.
That's the good stuff.
The same vintage I served
when you and Worf
got married.
It smells awful.
Ah...
it used to be your favorite.
I used to be
right-handed, too.
A lot of things
have changed
since I was joined.
I can imagine.
Seven lifetimes worth
of memories
would mix up anyone.
Or is it eight?
Who knows anymore?
It will be
a lot easier
once you get settled in.
Have you picked out
your quarters yet?
I'm not staying.
I'm going back to the Destiny
to be an Assistant Counselor.
You're a therapist?
Why does everyone
sound so surprised
when they hear that?
Oh, it's just, uh...
you're so young.
Why are you in such a hurry
to leave?
Why not stay for awhile
and get to know your
old friends again?
I don't want to force things.
People need time to get over
losing Jadzia.
Mm-hmm.
You know
something, Quark?
Besides Benjamin, you're
the only one of Jadzia's friends
who doesn't seem
uncomfortable around me.
She and I were close.
I don't see any reason
why we shouldn't be close, too.
Remember all those
late night tongo games?
Who could forget?
Hmm.
Wait a minute.
You owe me ten
strips of latinum
from our last game.
I don't think so.
Yes. I won with a full
consortium. I remember.
Your memory's playing
tricks on you.
Don't say that, Quark.
I'm confused enough as it is.
Look who's here.
I bet the two of you
have a lot to talk about.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Dax.
Are you alone?
Why are you
sneaking in this way?
I didn't want
to go through Ops
in case Worf was there.
We bumped into each other
last night at Quark's.
It didn't go well,
I take it.
You weren't expecting him
to accept you right away,
were you?
Of course not,
but he wouldn't
even talk to me.
Well, perhaps he was just
trying to honor your customs.
He knows that
the joined Trill aren't
supposed to get involved
with people who were married
to their previous hosts.
But that doesn't
mean that we can't
talk to each other.
Worf knows that.
Are you sure?
I told him all about
Trill traditions--
Jadzia did.
We discussed them--
they
discussed them.
I understand.
These pronouns are going
to drive me crazy.
Look at him,
Benjamin.
He's in pain.
How can you tell?
I was his wife.
I can tell.
I don't want to
put him through
any more heartache
than he's already
going through.
It's a good thing
I'm going back
to the Destiny.
You're still planning
on leaving?
I can't stay here.
I couldn't do that to him.
Besides, I think it might be
easier for me on the Destiny.
There are
too many memories here.
I'm going to miss you,
old man.
I'm going to miss you, too,
Benjamin.
If you feel that strongly,
Miles, it's all right.
You can be Crockett.
I'll be Travis.
And, and who am I
going to be again?
General Santa Anna.
Santa Anna.
When can our
costumes be ready?
Garak?
Hmm?
Our holosuite costumes?
When can they be ready?
Oh, I'm afraid you're going
to have to find them
from somewhere else.
The shop's closed.
Still?
Well, Starfleet Intelligence
is keeping me quite busy
these days.
Well, what if we let
you be Crockett?
Hey!
GARAK:
Even if I was
interested,
I don't have the time.
Do you have any idea
how long it takes to decode
a Cardassian military
transmission?
I mean, I invented
some of the basic
encryption protocols
when I was with Obsidian Order,
but it still takes me
several days
to decipher
the simplest sentence.
You've got to take
a break sometime.
Well, I intend to...
just as soon
as the Dominion is driven
off Cardassia.
Must you stand so close?!
That was a bit harsh.
Well, I don't like people
looming over me.
I have to get
back to work.
Thank you for your company,
gentlemen.
( heartbeat thudding )
( clearing throat )
( sighs )
( heartbeat intensifies )
( no audio )
( heartbeat continues )
( amplified heartbeat )
( distorted echoing breathing)
( no audio )
( groaning )
( breathes deeply )
( no audio )
I can't... breathe.
( groans )
Garak!
Odo to the Infirmary.
We have a medical
emergency.
Garak?
He had a claustrophobic attack
in his shop.
His shop?
I don't understand.
That's a
good-sized space.
I know. I've been
claustrophobic
for as long as
I can remember,
but lately,
it seems to have gotten worse.
Rooms that I once found
completely tolerable
now suddenly feel
alarmingly... cramped.
Well, I wish I had
an explanation,
but I don't.
He checks out fine.
Well, I don't
feel fine.
Would you gentlemen
mind terribly
if we continued
this conversation
on the Promenade?
( sighs )
Better?
A little.
Mr. Garak, as much
as I appreciate
your situation,
I'm not sure why
you asked to see me.
I was hoping you'd
be kind enough
to express my regrets to
Starfleet Intelligence.
When I get this way,
my concentration isn't
what it should be.
I'm afraid I
won't be decoding
any transmissions
for awhile.
Can I tell them
when to expect you
back on the job?
I wish I could say.
Believe me,
I'm not happy
about this, either.
I want to see an
end to this war
just as much as you.
And, now, if
you'll excuse me,
I'm going to
hem some pants.
For some reason, sewing
seems to calm me down.
Sewing?
We can't afford
to lose Mr. Garak right now.
Is there anything
you can do for him?
Well, to be blunt,
our friend Garak
needs his head examined.
Me? You want me to work
with Garak?
SISKO:
You're a counselor,
aren't you?
Assistant counselor.
I'm still in training.
Oh, come on, Dax,
what are you going
to learn
in the next few months
that you haven't
already learned
in the last 300 years?
Oh, how to keep
from breaking into tears
for no reason,
how to resist the urge
to stand on my head...
things like that.
Why are you standing
on your head,
by the way?
Emony used to do it.
The gymnast.
She found it relaxing.
Do you?
Actually, it's giving me
a headache.
( sighs )
Why can't Julian
work with Garak?
Oh, Julian's a good doctor,
but he's no counselor--
not even an
assistant counselor--
and besides,
he doesn't have
eight lifetimes' worth
of experience under his belt.
I bet he doesn't
stand on his head
for no reason, either.
That's a good point.
Oh, come on, old man,
you can do this.
All right.
I'll try.
I just wish I had as much
confidence in me as you do.
So, what do you think?
About what?
About her.
About who?
Dax.
Oh, Ezri.
She seems... nice.
Meaning what?
Meaning... nice.
Oh, come on, Doctor.
I know the way you felt
about Jadzia.
But she's
not Jadzia.
She's the next best thing.
So... are you
interested?
Sounds to me like
you're the one who's
interested, Quark.
It's not every day
you get a second chance
with a woman.
It's not the
same woman.
She's still Dax,
isn't she?
More or less.
Well, that's good
enough for me.
Ready for a little
competition?
You're insane.
And you...
( whispering ):
are going to lose.
EZRI:
Am I interrupting?
Ah...
You must be Ezri Dax.
The Captain told me
that you'd be dropping by
to counsel me.
Is that all right?
Well, it all depends
on what it involves.
I'm a very private person,
you know.
I understand.
So, is it helping?
The sewing...
is it making you
feel better?
Thankfully... yes.
You're lucky.
Nothing helps me.
Are you claustrophobic, too?
Why would you say that?
You just said...
No. I get spacesick...
ever since I was joined.
I'm very sensitive
to motion.
I can even feel the
station spinning.
Really?
It's because of what
happened to Torias.
He was killed in
a shuttle accident.
But why would that
make you spacesick?
Because I blame myself
for what happened.
You were piloting.
Yes. No.
Depends on
how you look at it.
Torias was my fifth host.
Didn't I say that?
Uh, no.
Well, he was,
and I think the reason
that his death has stayed
with me for so long
is because I just
can't seem to forgive him
for getting himself killed.
But you said it was an accident.
So, if he's not to blame,
then you're not
to blame, either.
I know, but somehow
I can't help but
punish myself for it.
By getting... spacesick.
Exactly.
Don't take this
the wrong way,
but it sounds to me
as if you're the one
who needs to see
a counselor.
You're probably right...
but I didn't come here
to talk about myself.
I came to talk about you.
So you did.
Do you remember
anything traumatic
happening to you
when you were young...
something involving
being trapped in
a confined space?
If I had been
that careless,
my father would have
left me there to
teach me a lesson.
Sounds like
he was strict.
He didn't get to be head
of the Obsidian Order
without a sense
of discipline.
Did he discipline you?
He punished me
when I misbehaved.
What father wouldn't?
Tobin.
Who?
My second host.
He could not bring himself
to discipline his children
no matter
what they did...
but... that's
another story.
How did you say that
your father punished you?
He'd lock me in a closet.
Why didn't you mention that
when I asked
if you'd ever been trapped
in a confined space?
I wasn't trapped.
I knew he'd let me out
as soon as I learned my lesson.
Learned your lesson?
Did you think you deserved
to be locked in that closet?
I could be very stubborn.
You blame yourself...
just like I blame myself
for that shuttle accident.
Maybe you get claustrophobic
for the same reason
that I get spacesick.
We're both punishing ourselves
for things that weren't
our fault.
That's it!
Don't you see?
We both have to let go
of all this misplaced guilt.
And if we do, our problems
will simply disappear?
Well, not overnight, but it's
a step in the right direction.
Well, I'll certainly
give your advice some thought.
Me, too.
( slowly exhaling )
Are you all right?
To tell the truth,
I'm starting to feel
a little claustrophobic.
Probably because we've
been talking about it.
Actually, I'm starting
to feel a little
spacesick myself.
If it's all
the same to you,
I think I'll go back
to my sewing.
Good idea.
Thank you
for stopping by.
My pleasure.
( groans softly )
Ooh...
Hello, Worf.
Ensign.
"Ensign"?
That's all you have
to say to me?
What more is
there to say?
I was your wife.
You are not Jadzia.
Jadzia died and
went to Sto-Vo-Kor.
I do not know you...
nor do I wish
to know you.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Dax?
Do you think the Chief could
adjust the inertial dampers
so that the station would
spin a little slower?
I don't know. Why?
( sighing ):
Never mind.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
I'm not going to say
"I told you so",
but Garak stopped by
Odo's office this morning
to pick up the latest
Cardassian transmissions
for decoding.
Really?
It looks like Garak's
claustrophobia is under control.
Huh.
I guess our talk helped him.
I told you so.
I thought you weren't going
to say that.
I couldn't resist.
Are you all right?
I talked with Worf.
He doesn't want to have
anything to do with me.
Perhaps I should have
a talk with him.
Absolutely not.
You intimidate him.
Me?
Don't tell him I told you.
( laughing ):
I intimidate Worf, huh?
You like that, don't you?
Of course not.
Come on.
I've been a man, I know.
Look, we're not talking
about me and Worf,
we're talking
about you and Worf.
Now, I sympathize
with what he's going through,
but as far as I'm concerned,
you have as much right
to be here as he does.
What are you getting at,
Benjamin?
The war...
has certainly not been very good
for morale around here.
I've been thinking...
the station could use
a good counselor.
I can't think of anyone
better suited for the job.
Thanks for saying that, but even
if Worf wasn't an issue,
I'm still just an
assistant counselor.
I took the liberty
of talking to
Starfleet Medical,
and they're willing to waive
the rest of your training
and give you a commission
as a full counselor
with the rank of Lieutenant.
How'd you talk them into that?
I asked them what
they thought you might learn
in the next few months--
That I haven't already learned
in the last 300 years.
They saw my point.
I hope you do, too.
( sighing ):
It means a lot to me
that you want me to stay,
but I can't.
Because of Worf?
Hmm... mostly.
Well... you just say the word,
and I will
intimidate him for you.
( laughing )
I'danian spice pudding.
No, cancel that.
I'll have a...
kilm steak, rare.
No. Tobin was a vegetarian.
( sighing )
Give me...
Two Fanalian
toddies...
hot.
How'd you know?
Lucky guess.
Care to join me?
Sure.
So, um...
here we are.
What was that?
What was what?
That look.
This might be
the last thing you want
to hear, but, uh...
you have Jadzia's eyes.
I'm sorry. I, um...
I shouldn't have said anything.
Don't flirt with me, Julian.
Please?
I'm not.
I remember how you used
to flirt with Jadzia.
I... it was just an observation.
Good, because I'm not like her.
She knew how to handle it.
Actually, she quite enjoyed it.
Really?
You didn't know?
Well, I-I... I always suspected.
You can be very charming.
You want to
know something?
If Worf hadn't come along,
it would've been you.
You really miss her,
don't you?
Yes.
I, uh...
I suppose I always will,
but, uh, somehow,
talking to you... seems to help.
Deputy Talpet to Dr. Bashir.
Go ahead.
We have a medical emergency
in Airlock 7.
It's Garak, sir.
I'm on my way.
He's down
there, Doctor.
Garak!
What is he
doing in there?
( grunting )
Garak, open the door!
( whispering ):
Let me out.
( birds calling )
EZRI:
Breathe in...
and out.
In...
Better?
Hmm... it's beautiful,
isn't it?
Look at that sky.
It just goes on and on.
But it doesn't.
It's an illusion.
There's a holosuite
wall not ten meters
in front of us.
But you can't see it.
I can feel it.
We could call up
another program.
I can't believe
the way I humiliated
myself back there.
I just... wanted
to get out.
I couldn't breathe.
Well, if you were looking
for fresh air,
you sure were knocking
on the wrong door.
I have to get this
situation under control.
If I can't, I'll be forced
to leave the station
and then where will I go?
I can't go back
to Cardassia.
I doubt if I'd be
welcome on... Bajor.
You're not going to have
to leave the station.
I'll talk to Quark
and tell him to leave
this holosuite available
to you 26 hours a day.
So the next time
you feel like jumping
out the nearest airlock--
come here instead.
It's going to be
all right.
We're going to get this
under control.
I promise.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to sit here
and be alone for a while.
I'll come and check in
on you later.
( shrieking )
Hold still.
( yells )
I think I've got something.
I knew it.
Never get a tympanic tickle
from an amateur.
A tympanic tickle?
Yeah. It's--
Never mind.
Uh, I don't want to know.
Hold still.
I'm going to get you
some antibiotics.
( sighing )
We need to talk.
About what?
( grunting )
Do not toy with me, Doctor.
I know how you
felt about Jadzia.
That was a long time ago.
I saw you with her.
Jadzia?
You know who I'm
talking about.
No, you've got it all wrong.
Stay away from her.
Now, wait just a minute.
You...
you have no right to tell me
who I can be friends with.
If you dishonor
Jadzia's memory...
you will regret it.
And that goes for you, too,
Ferengi.
What did I do?
( clattering and thumping )
Garak?
( grunting )
I thought you were going
to stay in the holosuite
for a while.
I got tired of staring
at a fake landscape,
pretending
I was outside.
No, no, no. Work
is the answer.
My father always
used to say
that people should
throw themselves
into their work.
"Do your chores, Elim.
I told you to do
your chores."
And if you didn't,
what would he do to you?
Oh, no, no, no.
Please, don't start.
Spare me your
insipid psychobabble.
I'm not some
quivering neurotic
who feels sorry for himself
because his daddy wasn't nice.
You couldn't begin
to understand me.
I'd like to try.
Oh, I'm sure
you would.
You'd like
nothing more
than to pry into
my personal affairs.
Well, I'm not interested
in dissecting my childhood.
I only want to save my people
from the Dominion.
I don't need someone to walk
in here and hold my hand.
I want someone
to help me get back to work.
And you, my dear,
are not up to this task.
I mean, look at you.
You're pathetic--
a confused child trying
to live up to a legacy
left by her predecessors.
You're not worthy
of the name "Dax."
I knew Jadzia.
She was vital, alive.
She owned herself,
and you...
you don't even know who you are.
How dare you presume
to help me?
You can't even help yourself.
Now, get out of here...
before I say something unkind.
( sobbing )
What's this all about?
What does it look like?
I'm resigning from Starfleet.
Why?
Because I can't
do my job.
Garak was right.
How can I help other people
when I can't even help myself?
I know this has been a hard
time for you, old man--
Don't call me that!
I'm not the old man.
I'm not Curzon or Jadzia.
No, you're Ezri, Ezri Dax,
and you've been given eight
lifetimes worth of experience.
Now, I know this
is confusing
for you right now,
but in time
you'll see
it's a wonderful gift.
It's a gift I don't deserve.
If that's the way you feel,
then go back to Trill
talk to
the Symbiosis Commission.
Maybe you can convince them
to take the symbiont out of you.
I wish they could, but removing
the symbiont would kill me.
You know that.
Well, if you're
leaving Starfleet,
you'll have to find
something to do.
Let's see...
maybe you could become
one of the people
who take care of
the symbiont pools.
It's quiet in those caves,
no one around,
no one expecting
great things of you.
You could spend the rest
of your life underground,
in the dark, stirring mud.
80 or 90 years
of that just might
be what you need.
And as for Dax...
that symbiont had
eight amazing lives.
So what if the
ninth was a waste?
Stop it, Benjamin.
I thought you of all people
would understand.
I do understand,
and you were right.
You don't deserve
the Dax symbiont.
Quite frankly,
you don't deserve to wear
that uniform.
I'll pass this on
to Starfleet Command. Dismissed.
( heavy sigh )
( door chimes )
Enter.
Oh, no, not again.
Compliments of Dr. Bashir.
He sent you.
No, that was
my idea.
Now, if you want
to skip the drinking
and get right down
to the talking, I'm game.
What is it you wish to discuss?
Julian swears there's nothing
going on between him and Ezri.
There's no reason
for you to be jealous.
This has nothing
to do with jealousy.
I know that Dr. Bashir
cared for Jadzia,
but this woman
is not Jadzia,
and treating her
as if she were
dishonors her memory.
Wrong. Treating
Ezri like a stranger
dishonors Jadzia's memory.
It doesn't make any sense.
She is not Jadzia, yet she is.
How can I honor the memory
of the woman I loved
when she is not really dead?
I don't have an answer
for you, Worf.
But let me ask you this:
How do you think Jadzia
would want you to treat Ezri?
There's no way to know.
Yes, there is,
and the person who can tell you
is the person
you've been avoiding
ever since she got here.
Well, I didn't think you'd
darken my doorstep again.
I just wanted to say
I'm sorry.
I wish I'd been able
to help you.
So do I.
Well, you don't have to worry
about me bothering you anymore.
I'll be leaving in the morning.
Yes. I had heard
that the Destiny  was
going to arrive tomorrow.
They're putting in
for supplies before
they head to the front,
but I won't be going with them.
I've decided
to go back to Trill.
How nice for you.
Actually,
the Destiny's
going to be joining
the Seventh Fleet at Kalandra.
Kalandra?
Those transmissions
you decoded last week
must have convinced Starfleet
that it's a good place
to launch a new offensive.
Yes, the transmissions
did indicate
that it was
somewhat vulnerable.
If the offensive
goes well,
Starfleet will have
you to thank for it.
Well, that's most gratifying.
I just thought you should know.
Are you all right?
Yes, of course, I'm all right.
That's very good news
about Kalandra.
Let's hope it goes well.
The Cardassians will put up
a strong fight.
Oh, indeed they will,
but in the end, they'll lose.
How can you be so sure?
Because they won't be
expecting an attack.
Because they have no idea
that I broke their code.
All those Cardassians are
going to die because of me.
I suppose that's one way
of looking at it.
What other way is there?
That by helping to end the war,
you'll be saving lives.
Saving lives? And what lives
would I be saving?
Human? Klingon? Romulan?
And Cardassian.
No, not Cardassians!
They're going to fight
to the bitter end.
The Dominion will see to that.
Don't you understand?
Don't you see?
I wanted to believe
that I was helping my people,
liberating them,
but all I've done
is to pave the way
for their annihilation.
I'm a traitor.
I've... betrayed...
everything!
( ragged gasping )
Dax to Infirmary.
I need a medical team.
How are you feeling?
Well, I'm breathing
much better now.
At least we found out
what's been triggering
these claustrophobic attacks
you've been having.
You know, when I first
agreed to help Starfleet,
I was... convinced
it was the right thing to do.
I didn't allow myself
to doubt it
even for an instant.
I never realized
how much it was gnawing at me.
I suppose
I was looking for a way out,
and the claustrophobia
gave me an excuse
to stop fighting my people.
Now that you know that,
what are you going to do?
Get back to work.
What else can I do?
The Dominion
must be stopped,
even if it does mean
the destruction of Cardassia.
The Captain will be glad to hear
that you're back on the job.
Well, he has you
to thank for it.
And so do I.
And what about you?
Are you still planning
to go back to Trill?
No. I'm going
to stay in Starfleet.
Well, I'm sure the Captain will
be glad to hear that as well.
The Captain.
Oh...
What now?
It's my request to be
reinstated into Starfleet.
I can't send this
to Starfleet Command.
Why not?
Because I never submitted
your resignation.
I had a feeling you didn't mean
all those things you said to me.
You were just trying
to rattle my cage.
You've done it to me
often enough.
I'm glad it worked.
Mr. Garak has asked
for the latest
Cardassian transmissions
to be sent to the Infirmary.
Well done.
Thanks.
Somehow I thought
you'd be happier that
I was staying in Starfleet.
I'd be happier if you would
stay here at DS9.
Me, too,
but you know I can't.
I hope Captain Raymer
knows how lucky she is.
She's getting
one hell of a counselor.
( door chimes )
Yes.
May I come in?
Of course.
I understand that you are
leaving in the morning.
That's right.
I am not certain
that I have treated you
the way that Jadzia
would have wanted.
You'll get no argument
from me there.
I loved her
with all my heart.
And she loved you.
Part of me is glad
to know that she
is not gone forever,
but, in some ways, it would
be easier if she were.
I know.
I heard that the Captain
offered you a position
as Station Counselor.
I... I would not want you
to decline on my account.
Worf, I can't stay.
I couldn't do that to you.
Do you wish to stay?
Very much.
Then do.
Jadzia would not have wanted you
to leave because of me.
Thank you.
It will be a long time
before I can accept
what has happened.
Until then...
You need your breathing room.
I understand.
Congratulations, Lieutenant.
I want you to take
a good look around.
You have just agreed
to take responsibility
for the mental health
of everyone in this room.
( all chuckle )
You have your work
cut out for you.
Well, I'm glad
they made you a Lieutenant.
It would have been hard
taking advice from an Ensign.
Since when did you
take advice from anyone?
Why don't you join us
for dinner tonight?
I don't want
to put you out.
Oh, no, please come.
It'll take the pressure off me.
All he does is sit there
and count how many times I chew.
I'll be there.
She is cute.
She is also about 300 years
too old for you.
I took the liberty
of putting a plate
together for you.
Thanks, Quark.
Uh, Worf isn't here, is he?
Good question.
Excuse me.
It's, uh, quite
a nice turnout.
Congratulations.
Oh, I hope it isn't
too crowded for you.
Oh, not at all.