Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead, Colonel.
Captain Solok of the Starship
T'Kumbra is here to see you.
Send him in.
Welcome to Deep Space 9,
Captain.
Your welcome is acknowledged.
Have a seat.
It's been a long time.
Ten years, two months,
five days.
You mean you don't know it
to the minute?
Of course I do, but humans are
often irked by such precision.
Especially the more
emotional humans.
Our repair list.
I understand
you were recently honored
with the Christopher Pike Medal
for Valor.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
And congratulations to you.
I heard you received your medal
last month.
My second, actually.
The T'Kumbra has been in combat
for over six months.
Spending time behind the lines
will be a welcome change.
This isn't exactly
a safe harbor.
We have seen
our share of action.
Of course you have.
We can upgrade
your inertial dampers
by the end of the day
but to begin to overhaul
your warp core
will take at least a week.
Oh, that is most inefficient.
War is an inefficient business.
A somewhat
unprofessional attitude.
However, I've come to expect
a lack of professionalism
and efficiency
on starbases run
by human officers.
You're welcome to take your ship
to a Vulcan station.
I think there's one
about 50 light-years away.
But if you're planning
to stay here with us...
behind the lines
then my Chief of Operations
will see to your requests.
Very well.
There is another matter
not listed on the formal report.
I need use of a holosuite.
The T'Kumbra holodecks
are currently under repair.
To arrange holosuite time,
you have to go through Quark.
He owns the only ones
on the station.
Then I will speak to Quark.
I have created a special program
for my senior staff
and they are quite eager
to resume using it.
Really?
Yes.
In fact, you may find
the program of some interest.
It is based on an Earth game.
And what game would that be?
Colonel, assemble
the senior staff
in the Wardroom now.
As you probably know,
the Starship T'Kumbra
is docked at our station.
What you may not know
is that their Captain
considers his crew...
an all Vulcan crew, by the way...
to be the finest in the fleet.
I happen to think that
the people sitting at this table
comprise the finest crew
in the Quadrant.
You're not going to get
much of an argument
from this group.
I didn't think so.
Which is why when their Captain
challenged us to a contest
of courage, teamwork
and sacrifice
I accepted on your behalf.
We will destroy them.
I was hoping for that reaction.
So when is
this clash of the titans?
Two weeks in Holosuite 5.
What's the contest?
Baseball.
"Chapter 25:
The infield fly rule
"is invoked in instances where
"with both first base
and second base occupied
"or with first, second
and third base occupied...
What if there is
a runner at home?
There's never a runner at home.
Okay, uh..."and
fewer than two outs
the batter hits a high fly..."
"Fly: The term
for a batted ball
while it is in the air."
Oh, right.
Uh, uh, "fewer than two outs
"the batter hits a high fly...
"which in the judgment
of the umpire
"can readily be caught
by an infielder
"or the pitcher or catcher
inside fair ground.
"The batter is then called out
regardless of whether the ball
is subsequently caught or not."
That seems simple enough.
"An attempt to bunt
"however, under the
conditions noted above
"which results in a fair fly
shall not be regarded
an infield fly."
What's a bunt?
A bunt:
A ball that has been
deliberately tapped
into the area between
the pitcher and the catcher
by the batter in order to force
the fielding side
to throw out the batter
and allow a runner to advance.
Right.
Chief, what's a grand slam?
Uh... a home run that's hit
when the bases are crowded.
Right,
except it's "bases loaded."
Now...
what's a "Fancy Dan"?
You're making that up.
I most certainly am not.
Hi.
Jake told us about the game
against the Vulcans.
It sounds really exciting.
You should come watch.
"Fancy Dan: A fielder who puts
an extra flourish
"on his movements
while making a play
in hopes of gaining the approval
of the spectators."
Actually, we were
thinking of doing
more than watching.
If we can.
That is, if there's still room
for other potential players
to possibly try and...
We want to try out.
Nog always talks about
how Captain Sisko
and Jake play baseball
and how it brings them
closer together.
Since Nog and I
haven't seen much
of each other lately
I thought this might
be a good way
of spending some time together.
And I decided to make it
a complete family outing.
That is so sweet.
Isn't it?
Idiotic is what it is.
You're going to make a fool
out of yourself.
I will not.
You can barely spin a dabo wheel
much less kick a ball
around a field.
Shows how much you know.
You don't kick the ball...
do you?
You won't make the team.
At least we're trying out.
What about you?
I don't have the slightest
interest in this hu-man game.
You know why?
Jake says it's a game
that takes heart
and you sold yours
a long time ago.
Come on, Rom.
What time are tryouts?
1300, Holosuite 4.
Hey, hey!
All right!
Ha, ha, whoo!
Yes!
First day of practice
and it's an exciting time!
Am I right?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah! There we go.
There we go.
That's the spirit!
Now, first let me introduce
you to our pitcher
and our secret weapon,
Jake "The Slider" Sisko!
Good luck, Jake.
- The Slider.
- Very nice.
Now, all the other positions
are still open for tryouts.
Now, every one of you here today
has seen at least
one baseball game
with me in the holosuite.
Now, I know it looks simple...
you throw the ball, you catch
the ball, you hit the ball...
but it is not that easy.
It's a difficult game.
It was a difficult game to play
even for seasoned professionals
who spent their
lifetime practicing.
And now we have
less than two weeks
to build a team
and to face the opponent.
Now, I know
what some of you are thinking.
"How are we going to beat
the Logicians?
"They're all Vulcans.
"They're stronger and faster
than any one of us...
"except for Worf
and our genetically
enhanced doctor."
But there is more to baseball
than physical strength.
It's, uh...
it's about courage...
and it's also about faith
and it is also about heart
and if there's one thing
our Vulcan friends lack,
it's heart.
I think we can beat them.
I know we can beat them.
Yep.
We are going to beat them!
- Am I right?
- Yeah!
I can't hear you.
Yes, sir!
Are we going
to beat the Vulcans?
I can't hear you!
Yes, sir!
All right, then.
Let's play some baseball!
First, I want you
to pair off.
Spread yourselves
about ten meters apart
and, uh, play some catch.
Have fun.
Yeah. Just a little, uh,
throw and catch.
Nice and easy.
You almost had it.
I said, throw it here.
Don't throw it to her.
You've got to throw it
to someone who's looking at you.
Oh, come on, Quark.
This is going to be
two long, hard weeks.
Jake, I don't care
how hard and long
these two weeks are
but I'm not going
to lose to Solok
in a baseball game.
We are going to win.
Umpire?
That's right.
Will you do it?
Well, wouldn't
a holographic umpire
be more accurate?
I don't want a computer program
calling a baseball game.
That's something Solok
would do.
I want a real person
behind the plate
not just some collection
of photons and magnetic fields.
I-I-I also want a person who
can be completely impartial
and I can't think
of anyone I trust more.
Well, that's, uh...
that's very flattering.
Oh, it's the truth.
Will you do it?
All right.
Outstanding.
Here are the rules.
Uh, if you have any questions
I'll be with the team
in the Infirmary.
The Infirmary?
Ah, we had a few problems
at practice today.
Remember, the game is
in less than two weeks.
So you better start
to, uh, work on your moves.
My moves?
I can't believe this.
I used to be an athlete.
At least, I remember
being an athlete.
My third host, Emony,
was an Olympic gymnast.
I keep expecting my legs
to react like hers did
but I fell all over myself.
It's like I don't know
my own body anymore.
I don't know what
you're complaining about.
At least you didn't
require major surgery.
Knitting together
a couple of bones
is not major surgery, Quark.
It is if the bones
are in the back of your skull.
I hope you learned
your lesson.
Always look behind you
before swinging a bat.
So, how are my casualties doing?
We'll live.
If you believe Julian.
Personally, I'm not sure
I'm going to make it.
That's the spirit, old man.
Don't lose your sense of humor.
Hey, Chief, how's the shoulder?
He's out, I'm afraid.
His rotator cuff was badly torn.
Can't you repair the damage?
I need him on third,
and he's anchoring
the second half of the lineup.
I've repaired
the rotator cuff
but the ligaments need time
to knit together
with the clavicular joint.
I can't let him play baseball.
Damn!
I'm sorry, sir.
I was really looking
forward to the game.
Well, there's an old saying...
"those who can't... coach."
As for now, you are batting,
pitching and first base coach.
Oh, great.
Which one is first base?
We'll go over that again later.
All right. Practice
tomorrow morning at 0730.
Don't be late.
We'll be there.
Well, if you excuse me
I still have to realign
Worf's zygomatic bone.
Ow.
Tell him I'm sorry.
Ah, we can move Ezri
over to third.
No, no, no,
I need her in center.
Ooh! I know who we can get.
I'll have to pull some strings,
but I think I can do it.
Who?
Welcome home.
Oh, music to my ears.
Mmm. Does this mean
you missed me?
Like a piece
of my heart was missing.
Oh, sweet words.
And flowers, too?
Are you feeling all right?
Now that you're back,
I feel outstanding.
Oh, I could get used to this.
And well you should... are
you going to be here long?
Um, as a matter of fact
my next three cargo runs
have been reassigned.
Really?
Oh, bureaucrats...
who knows why they do anything?
Who knows?
So...
what are we going to do
with all my time off?
I have a few ideas.
I bet you do.
So tell me
how's your throwing
arm holding up?
There you go, Kas!
That's what I'm talking about.
All right.
Head's up, people.
There's a runner on first,
one away.
I got it!
I got it! I got it!
Oh!
How many is that?
Today?
I think he's missed ten.
Damn.
All right. Batting practice.
What's he doing here?
He's scouting us.
If he is taking the time
to conduct reconnaissance
he must be worried.
He should be.
Next week on this field,
that man is going to get
a painful lesson in humility.
Batter up.
Today, I'm going
to hit the ball.
You just watch.
Oh!
All right, Rom,
remember what we talked about.
Keep your eye on the ball.
Follow the ball
from the pitcher's hands
all the way to the bat.
Oh!
Sorry.
You can do it.
Hang in there, Rom.
All right, Rom.
Oh-oh.
Sorry.
That's it.
You're done.
I'll do better tomorrow,
Captain.
No, you won't.
You are finished. Gone.
Off the team.
Sir, can't you give him
another chance...
Is anyone talking to you,
Ensign?
I can't play?
That's the smartest
thing you said all week.
You can't play.
Now, get your gear.
Get out of here.
Worf, you're up.
Captain Sisko hates me.
He doesn't hate you, Rom.
Sisko was just
blowing off steam.
He'll get over it.
That's right.
I'll go talk with
him in the morning.
Maybe he'll change his...
No! I don't want him to kick
you off the team, too.
I don't care about the team.
If you can't play,
I won't, either.
- Oh, that goes for me, too.
- And me.
And us.
Benjamin was way
out of line today, Rom.
Yeah. This game is
supposed to be fun
not a life-and-death struggle.
So we've decided to quit
unless he reinstates
you immediately.
No! Please!
Rom...
we're on your side.
I don't want to make
the team like this.
I had my chance,
but I wasn't good enough.
Let's face it...
the Captain's right.
I'm hopeless.
I don't deserve
to be on the team.
You play.
You've earned it.
Playing baseball doesn't
mean anything to me.
But it should.
You're good at it.
So are you, and I
want to see you play.
I want to see all of you play.
I want to see our team
beat the Vulcans
even if I'm only watching
from the... the, uh...
The stands.
Right.
Please?
If, uh... that's the way
you feel about it.
Rom, there are moments
when I know exactly
why I married you.
What are you eating?
I'm not eating.
I'm chewing.
Chewing what?
Gum. It's traditional.
I had the replicator
create me some.
They just chewed it?
No, they infused
the gum with flavor.
What did you infuse it with?
Scotch.
Here. Try some.
Hmm.
All right.
You got a runner on first.
You got a runner on second.
One away. Ground ball
to the second baseman.
Kira, what do you do?
I go for the double play
unless the runner
on third is already
on his way home, in which case...
Okay, relax
and keep your weight
on the balls of your feet.
Back elbow up.
Yeah. Good.
Yeah.
Faster.
Come on, come on.
Faster. Come on,
come on...
Come on! Come on!
Faster!
Ooh, yeah! Good!
- I got it!
- Mine!
I got it!
Well, don't look at me!
- You called it!
- You should have got it.
- I was out of position!
- That was yours all the way!
Oh, come on, Julian.
Safe!
You're out!
Oh, that's quite a knot.
Your back is like a minefield
of bruised muscles.
You tell me something
I don't know. Ow!
Okay.
You're lifting your foot up
at the plate.
What?
Okay. Take a swing.
Wait.
Stop.
Right there. Look.
You're lifting your foot
in the backswing.
It's been messing up
your whole rhythm.
Not that bad.
I know that look.
It's the I'd-really-
like-to-smash-something-
but-she'll-think-I'm-crazy look.
Well, don't let me stop you.
They're your quarters.
Smash away,
if it'll make you feel better.
The only way I'll
feel better
is to beat Solok tomorrow.
So, do I get to hear
the Solok story now?
And before you say no,
you'd better consider the fact
that if you don't tell me,
you won't have a third baseman.
We were in the same class
at the Academy, you know.
One weekend I was
with some friends
at an off-campus bar...
the Launching Pad...
and Solok came in
with some Vulcan Cadets
who said
they were doing research
on illogical
human bonding rituals.
We didn't take kindly to that.
And you'd... had a few drinks.
Yeah... one or two.
Well, we got into a debate,
and Solok said
that Vulcans were
naturally superior to humans
and other "emotionally
handicapped" species.
Of course, I took
the opposite position.
So... there I am...
drunk... and debating
logic versus emotion
with a smug...
and very sober Vulcan.
Well, to make
a long story short, I decided
that the best way to prove
that humans were every bit
the equal of Vulcans
was to challenge him
to a wrestling match.
Wrestling?
All I wanted to do
was to wipe that arrogant look
off his face
so in the heat of the moment...
I challenged him.
And?
I, uh... ended up
in the Infirmary...
with a separated shoulder,
two cracked ribs
and a very bruised ego.
Oh, Ben...
I don't... no, I
don't mean to laugh
but... what did you expect?
A Vulcan has three times
the strength of a human.
And they're faster, too.
But you're right.
I got what I deserved.
And if it had ended right there
it would've been fine,
but it didn't.
Solok took every opportunity
to remind me of our match.
He used to point me out whenever
I walked across the campus.
In fact, he wrote
five psychology papers
about our match.
I became the living embodiment
of why Vulcans were
inherently superior to humans.
You don't mean he was gloating?
A Vulcan?
That's exactly what I mean.
He may have hidden it
beneath that Vulcan calm
but... he loved
every minute of it.
And you'd think
that once we graduated
it would've stopped,
but it didn't.
Over the years,
Solok wrote over a dozen papers
on Vulcan/human
comparative profiles...
and in the beginning
of every paper...
is an analysis of that...
damned wrestling match.
And now he comes to your station
and announces
that he's put together
a baseball team.
He doesn't care about baseball.
All he wants to do is to rub
my nose in it one more time
but now he is using my game.
My game!
You should tell that
to the Niners.
They don't understand
why you're so caught up in this.
Oh, no, I'd rather they think
I'm just caught up
in some baseball game
than pursuing...
an adolescent rivalry.
Just tell them the truth.
They'll understand.
They need to know how personal
this is to you.
Oh, no.
No.
I mean it.
And you can't tell them, either.
I want you to promise me.
All right.
I promise.
He made me promise
not to tell you
so you'll have to keep this
under your hats.
Curzon and Jadzia
always wondered why
Benjamin hated Solok
but he'd never talk about it.
Well, he's embarrassed.
He's calling it
an "adolescent rivalry"
but Solok's the one
that's kept this thing going.
And now he's trying
to beat the Captain
at his own game.
It is a dishonorable motive.
I'm beginning
to hate him myself.
So, what are we going
to do about it?
I tell you what we do.
We go out there tomorrow
and we put that Vulcan
in his place.
We win it for the Captain.
And for all our "emotionally
handicapped" races.
Now, there's something
worth fighting for, right?
- Niners!
Okay, laddies, let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
Let's show these guys.
Look, let's, uh, dispense
with the crowd.
My team has never played
in front of people before.
If you wish.
Computer, eliminate
the spectators.
Play ball!
Batter up!
All right, Niners,
Let's hear some chatter.
Hey, batter, batter,
batter, batter, batter!
Hey, batter, batter, batter,
batter, batter, batter, batter!
Death to the opposition.
Hey, batter, swing, batter.
Strike him out!
Lucky swing.
All right.
Hey, don't worry.
You'll get the next one, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
You're making mental
errors out there.
Stupid mistakes.
You have to start thinking
about what you're doing.
Colonel, you have
to charge the ball.
Don't wait for it
to come to you.
Ezri, you're playing too deep!
They rattled you.
Yeah. They're pretty good.
What are you talking about,
they're pretty good?
You better stop admiring them
and start striking them out!
Batter up!
Let's play ball.
Strike three.
Let's go!
Out!
You want to try that again?
Hey, hey, hey!
Colonel, stay cool.
Don't do anything
to get yourself thrown out.
Wouldn't dream of it, Captain.
You're out, by the way.
Play ball!
Was that slide at second legal?
'Fraid so.
Doesn't seem very sporting.
These guys are playing to win.
Sporting doesn't enter into it.
Safe!
It's about time.
Strike one.
If it's not there, let it go.
All right!
Don't reach for it.
Ball one.
Hey, now!
Good eye, Worf!
Good eye!
Ball two.
Remember what we talked about.
Keep your eye on the ball.
Foul ball. Strike two.
Big stick!
Good eye, Worf.
Good eye.
Ball three.
Time.
Time!
Let's go, batter.
Do not rush me.
Strike three!
What?! What are you
talking about?
That ball was at least
a half a meter out!
How can you call it a strike?
Reverse the call!
That was low and outside.
The ball was clearly outside.
Oh, what the hell
were you looking at?
You can't tell me
that ball was over the plate.
What were you doing,
regenerating?
Caught the outside corner.
Outside corner?!
Maybe the corner of the dugout!
That was a ball and you know it!
We should have two men on!
Two men on! Two men on!
Gentlemen,
you are trying my patience.
You stole a run from us.
You stole it
just as if you reached up
and tore it off
the scoreboard!
You stole it from us!
You... you're outta here!
What?!
"No player shall at any time
make contact with the
umpire in any manner."
The prescribed penalty
for the violation is
immediate ejection
from the game.
Rule number 4.06, subsection
"A", paragraph four.
Look it up,
but do it in the stands.
You're gone!
It was a ball.
That was no strike.
I know it was a ball.
Chief?
What?
I think that means
you're in charge now.
You're right.
Well, what are you
standing around for?
You never seen a man
thrown out of the game?
Come on.
Get your gloves on
and get in that field!
Let's go! Come on!
Quark! Wake up!
You're in right.
Julian, you're on second.
Leeta, you're in left.
Come on.
Let's go, let's go.
We got a game to play.
Come on! Move it!
Play ball.
Ball one.
Strike one!
Back, Ezri, back!
Go, go, go!
All right!
Yeah!
Y-y-y-y-yes!
Now that is a Fancy Dan.
All right!
Batter up!
Home! Worf!
Bring it home!
What's wrong?
He didn't touch home, Nog.
Is that true?
W-what do I do?!
Find him and kill him!
Just tag him out.
Jake, cover home.
Which one?
Tag them all.
Come on, Nog, hurry up.
No. Tag the next one.
Jake!
He's out!
You're out!
Yeah, Nog, well done!
- Yeah!
He's out.
Did you see that?
That's what I love
about this game.
You never know
what's going to happen next.
Every situation is different,
huh?
It looks like a lot of fun.
Rom... come here.
Let's go.
Where are we going?
Safe!
Do it, come on! Come on!
Hey, come on, Jake!
You can do it!
Come on!
Chief! Chief! Chief!
Call time out.
Why?
You're making a substitution.
What?
- Time!
You're up, Rom.
Oh, you've got to be kidding.
We got man on third.
We could score.
Sit down, Quark.
Go ahead, Rom.
You can do it.
All right, Dad!
Come on, you can do it!
Okay, go.
Let's play ball!
Computer...
Come on, Rom.
Go, Rom.
Your attention, please.
Now pinch-hitting for
Jake Sisko, number 13: Rom.
Come on, Dad!
You can do it.
I hope.
Strike one.
Come on, Dad.
Come on, Rom.
You can do it.
Strike two!
It's okay, Rom.
Julian.
What was that thing called...
you know, when you just
tap the ball down the baseline?
Uh, bunt?
That's it... a bunt.
We've got to give him
the sign.
Rom!
What?
Go!
Rom... run!
Keep going, Rom!
Safe!
All right, Rom!
Rom! Rom! Rom!
Umpire, this is
completely improper.
The game is not over.
You're gone!
That was great, Dad!
A great bunt!
Hey, Jake, that was
a hell of a game.
A hell of a game.
I gave up ten runs.
They're Vulcans.
If they were humans
you'd have held them
to just two or three.
Well, when you
put it that way...
Yes.
Now, pardon me.
I owe you an apology.
No.
Unless you really want to.
I'm sorry.
Apology accepted.
If you have some time,
one day
maybe you can teach me
how to bunt.
Sure.
What's a bunt?
Oh.
That's my dad.
I fail to see why
you are celebrating.
The Ferengi's bunt
was an accident
and you still lost the game.
You are absolutely right
and I couldn't be happier.
Quark, a round of drinks
for the house
on my tab.
I'm way ahead of you, Captain.
You are attempting
to manufacture a triumph
where none exists.
I'd say he succeeded.
To manufactured triumph.
Manufactured triumph.
Hear, hear!
This is a typical human reaction
based on emotionalism
and illogic.
Did I hear irritation
in that voice?
Certainly not.
That sounded positively
defensive to me.
With a hint of anger.
And just a touch of jealousy.
And a lot of bitterness.
Are you always this emotional?
I refuse to engage in this...
human game of taunting.
Human?
Did I forget to wear
my spots today?
All that intelligence
and he doesn't know
what a human looks like.
Captain...
here's something else
for your desk.
Well...
will you look at that?
Would you like to sign it?
No.
Oh, my.
Yes.