Miles, fancy a drink?
I can‘t.
Keiko and the kids
are waiting on me for dinner.
Next Thursday--
book a holosuite.
They‘re going to Bajor.
Hi, Julian.
Hi.
You going to Vic‘s?
Yes.
Mind if I join?
Uh... actually, we
were looking forward
to spending
an evening alone.
Great.
Well, have a great time.
I understand.
Cheeky virus.
You‘ve gone and mutated on me.
Well, you can run,
but you can‘t hide.
Lights.
Nog to Dr. Bashir.
Go ahead.
You‘re needed
in the Infirmary, sir.
It‘s 3:00 in the morning.
Isn‘t Dr. Girani on duty?
Not anymore.
Admiral Patrick threw her out.
Admiral who?
He wants to see you
immediately, sir.
On my way.
( door opens )
What‘s going on, Ensign?
Sir, Admiral Patrick
and his staff
just arrived
on the Farragut.
What happened
to Dr. Girani?
The Admiral said
she was asking
too many stupid
questions.
Dr. Bashir reporting
as ordered.
Finally.
Patrick?!
That‘s Admiral Patrick.
Mind your manners,
Doctor.
What are you
doing here?
That‘s a stupid question.
Where did you get
those uniforms?
That‘s a stupid question, too.
Please excuse
the doctor, sir.
He just woke up.
They‘re not
Starfleet officers, Nog.
They‘re not?
We‘re mutants.
Genetically
engineered mutants.
Can‘t you tell?
BASHIR: Does anybody
at the Institute
know you‘re missing?
That‘s a stupid...
Will you stop saying that!
Why are you
so upset?
You wanted Sarina
brought here. Well...
here she is.
( sighs )
I was considering bringing
Sarina here for treatment
when I was ready,
but I still have to modify
my surgical equipment
before I can begin
the procedure.
Well, don‘t worry--
we‘ll help you.
And when we‘re through
with Sarina,
she will be just like us.
Do you have any idea
how much trouble you could
get into for impersonating
Starfleet officers?
Jack, you didn‘t say
anything about us
getting into trouble.
Well, we didn‘t get
caught, did we?
Didn‘t anybody
question you?
Of course. But when they did,
Patrick would say...
That‘s a stupid...
You‘d be surprised
how well it works.
I‘ll say.
What are they
going do to us?
Oh, it‘s all right.
I‘ll find a way
to straighten this
out... somehow.
Hello, Sarina.
Remember me?
Of course
she remembers you.
She‘s not an idiot.
She‘s just a little
cataleptic.
Are you really
going to be able
to make her better?
I‘m going to do
everything I can.
I promise.
They posed as an Admiral
and his staff.
If you want me to convince
Starfleet not to press charges,
you‘re going to have to give me
a damn good reason.
They wanted
to bring Sarina here
so that I could help her.
They meant well.
They meant well?
That‘s the same
excuse you gave me
when they were caught
trying to pass military
secrets to the Dominion.
They were trying
to save lives...
Doctor, I appreciate
that you feel a
connection to them
because you are genetically
engineered yourself,
but they have displayed
a consistent disregard
for the rules
that the rest of
society lives by.
Maybe that‘s because
they‘re not allowed
to live in society.
We are not here
to debate Federation policy
toward
the genetically enhanced.
We are here to discuss
what to do about these people
now that they‘re aboard.
Of course.
Well, with your
permission, sir,
I would like to proceed
with Sarina‘s treatment.
I take it the Institute
has given the approval
to move forward?
A copy of the medical
protocols I submitted.
Dr. Loews,
Sarina‘s legal guardian,
has given her consent.
Well, it appears that
this procedure has never
been done before.
Well, there‘s no guarantee
that it will work, of course,
but if it does, it could change
everything for her.
There‘s no reason
to think that she‘s suffering
from the same type
of behavioral disorders
as Jack and the others.
Her problem is that she‘s
trapped inside her own mind.
This could free her.
There are still a few technical
issues I have to work on,
but I feel confident
that I can iron them all out.
You‘ve put in a lot of time
on this, haven‘t you?
I owe it to her, sir.
I could have ended up
the same way as Sarina,
but I was lucky.
My DNA re-sequencing
didn‘t have
any unintended side effects.
All right, Doctor.
I‘ll take care of Starfleet.
You take care of Sarina.
Thank you, sir.
I‘ll arrange to have
the rest of the people
sent back to the Institute.
Actually, I was hoping
you‘d allow them to stay
on for awhile.
For what reason?
Sarina‘s spent the last
15 years with them.
Now, assuming
the procedure works
and she comes out
of her isolation,
I think it would be
helpful to have some
familiar faces around.
Well, we‘ll arrange
for quarters
to be set up in
the cargo bay.
I appreciate it.
Just make sure
they stay there.
I don‘t want them to get
out and cause trouble
like they did the last time.
I‘ll see that it
doesn‘t happen again.
I‘ll hold you to that.
One thing more.
Get them out
of those uniforms.
Aye, sir.
There. Don‘t you
look pretty?
JACK:
Why are we doing
this anyway?
PATRICK:
Keep going.
JACK:
Here?
A little to the left.
That‘s not where
it was last time.
Oh, what difference
does it make?
He‘s right.
Fine.
How‘s that?
Much better.
Here he is!
Well, well, what did
the Captain say?
All systems are a go.
See? See?
I told you it was a good
idea to bring her here.
That‘s right, Jack,
I remember.
So, when do
we operate?
We?
You‘re going to
need some help.
Oh, so you‘re
a surgeon now?
How hard
can it be?
Um, thanks
for the offer, but...
Oh, I get it.
You want to take
all the credit.
It‘s not about credit.
It‘s about what‘s best
for Sarina, I think.
Fine. I‘m busy, anyway.
New project.
Oh, glad to hear it.
What are you working on?
Wouldn‘t you
like to know?
( chuckling )
Well, I‘ll leave you to it,
but, uh, do me a favor
and, uh, change out
of those uniforms.
Sarina, I‘d like to take
you to the Infirmary
and run a few tests.
Is that all right?
She‘s afraid it‘s going to hurt.
It won‘t hurt.
I promise.
You‘re in good hands...
very good hands.
Don‘t get your
hopes up, Julian.
It‘s over
between the two of us.
I have a new man in my life...
that gorgeous
little Ferengi.
Nog?
Jealous?
Oh, that‘s so sweet.
Hurry back.
BASHIR:
Sarina‘s cerebral cortex
was genetically enhanced
in order to accelerate
the rate at which she can
process information.
Now, the only problem is,
her visual and auditory systems
can‘t channel the stimuli
into the cortex fast enough,
so, because
they‘re out of sync
she can‘t focus on
what‘s going on around her.
Well, is there any way
to get her sensory
processors up to speed?
I need to stimulate
the growth of new synapses
in the thalamus,
which means...
I have to manipulate
neural proteins
at a subatomic level.
Well, then you‘ve
got a problem.
This is the most advanced
neocortical probe made,
and it‘s not nearly
that accurate.
Now you know why
I asked you down here.
Well, I wish I could
help you, Julian,
but at resolutions
that small,
quantum fluctuations are
impossible to control,
and I can‘t make this
thing any more accurate.
How can you say that before
you‘ve even tried it?
I‘m sorry, Julian.
It-it-it can‘t be done.
I‘m sorry.
Well, sorry just isn‘t
good enough, Miles.
This is Sarina‘s
only chance at living
a normal life.
Julian, I can‘t break
the laws of physics.
Nobody can.
Your friend was right.
You can‘t break
the laws of physics.
ALL:
But you can bend them.
JACK:
We recalibrated
the imaging diodes.
It is so accurate
that you could clip
the wings of an angel
dancing on the
head of a pin.
Uh... if you wanted to.
Anything?
( sighs )
Sarina?
Now, just how am I
supposed to know
you understand me
if you don‘t give
me some sign, hmm?
Anything.
It doesn‘t matter
how small.
It‘s been five days now,
and she‘s just
as unresponsive
as she was before
the procedure.
I know you‘re
disappointed, Julian,
but you did everything
that you could.
Well, it
wasn‘t enough.
I‘m sorry.
Obviously, you want
to punish yourself.
Do you want help?
Because I‘m really good
at punishing myself.
Let‘s see...
if I were you,
I‘d be kicking myself
for making promises
I couldn‘t keep,
for getting
people‘s hopes up,
for being arrogant
enough to think
that I could help Sarina,
even though dozens
of other doctors have failed.
Should I
keep going?
No.
That just about
covers it. Thanks.
Glad I could help.
What is it?
I‘m not sure.
Excuse me.
Sarina?
What are you
looking at?
Every...thing.
( halting nasal monotone):
You... heard me.
I thought something
and you heard it.
Sarina...
you spoke.
Sarina.
Come and sit down.
I need to run
a few tests.
( beeping quietly )
( gasps softly )
What is it?
Listen.
( beeping )
It‘s nice.
You‘re right.
I hadn‘t noticed
that before.
That‘s a little odd.
Her norepinephrine levels
are slightly elevated.
What‘s causing it?
I‘m not sure.
It‘s probably due to
limbic overcompensation.
The levels should drop
when the new thalamic
connections stabilize.
You‘re right... I think.
I was listening when you
were telling the nurses
about the procedure.
I kept thinking that
I wanted to thank you
for what you were
trying to do for me...
and now I finally can.
Thank you.
Did you move this?
Maybe I did,
maybe I didn‘t.
Would you leave
him alone?
Patrick, it‘s where
it‘s supposed to be.
Oh...
( nasal monotone ):
Hello, everyone.
Did you hear what she said?
Did you hear that?
I don‘t think I‘ve heard
a more beautiful
sound in my life.
It was my idea
to bring you here!
We missed you!
You look so different!
Aren‘t you going
to say thank you?
Did the surgery hurt?
There‘s so much I want
to say to all of you.
Why are you
talking like that?
Quiet!
( imitates Sarina ):
There‘s so much I want
to say to all of you...
There‘s so much...
Jack!
No, he‘s right.
I can hear the
way I sound.
Don‘t worry.
It‘s only temporary.
It just takes a little practice.
Practice!
Ah, practice. Good idea.
Listen to this, Sarina.
( sings scale ):
♪ Do, re, mi, fa, so,
la, ti, do. ♪
( sings same note ):
♪ Do, re, mi, fa,
so, la, ti, do. ♪
Are you tone deaf?
You‘re the one
who‘s tone deaf.
( sings scale ):
♪ Do, re, mi, fa, so,
la, ti, do. ♪
( sings mostly in tune ):
♪ Do, re, mi, fa, so,
la, ti, do. ♪
Much better.
♪ Do, re, mi, fa, so,
la, ti... ♪
♪ Do, re, mi, fa,
so, la, ti... ♪
( low octave ):
♪ Do. ♪
( laughing )
Yes, yes-yes-yes.
Let‘s improvise.
Lauren.
♪ Do, re, mi, do, re, mi... ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi... ♪
♪ Fa, mi,
re, do ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪Fa... ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪Fa ♪
♪Fa, mi,
re, do ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do. ♪
( Bashir applauds )
Molto allegro.
( in unison ):
♪ Do, re, mi, do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi, do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, so, la, so ♪
♪ Re, mi, fa, mi ♪
♪ Do, re, mi, do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, mi ♪
♪ Re, do, re, mi, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ La, so, fa, so ♪
♪ Fa, mi,
re, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ La, ti, do ♪
♪Fa, so, la, so ♪
♪ So, do, ti, do, so, mi,
fa, so, la ♪
♪ So ♪
♪ Do, re, mi, do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, so, la, so ♪
♪ So, fa, so ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do ♪
( all singing
complex harmonies )
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, so, ti, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ So, fa, so... ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ Fa, mi, re, do ♪
♪ Do, re, mi,
do, re, mi ♪
♪ Do, mi, so, la ♪
♪ Fa, mi,
re, do ♪
♪ So... ♪
ALL:
♪ Do. ♪
It was amazing.
Within a few minutes,
Sarina‘s voice just took off.
That kind of improvement
usually takes weeks
of speech therapy.
That is amazing.
Julian...
So, she was exhausted.
I took her back
to the Infirmary.
I needed to monitor her neural
activity anyway while she slept,
but I still can‘t get
over that transformation.
Yesterday, she was
silent as a stone.
Today, she‘s singing
and laughing...
You should have seen her, Miles.
How could I? I‘ve been
sitting here all night.
Is it Thursday?
Well, why else would I
be sitting here all night?
Oh...
I‘m sorry. I forgot.
It‘s all right.
Morn caught me up
on how his 17 brothers
and sisters are doing.
I‘d better head off.
I got an early start
in the morning.
Oh, I‘m sorry
about the mix-up, Miles.
Mmm.
It‘s all right.
I‘m happy for her.
Happy for both of you.
( humming softly )
Sarina.
What are you doing here?
How did you get in?
It wasn‘t hard.
Your access code
only has six digits.
Is something wrong?
I-I couldn‘t sleep.
My nurse could have given
you something for that.
I... don‘t want
to sleep.
Why not?
What if I wake up
the way I was?
What if I can‘t...
It‘s not going to happen.
Your life‘s going
to be different now.
Your future...
is full of possibilities.
You know, you‘re going
to be doing things
that you haven‘t
even dreamed of.
There‘s really no
reason to be afraid.
Sarina?
( sighs )
Good morning.
Morning.
You didn‘t account
for the L-Two codon.
What?
That‘s why
the virus mutated.
You need to target
the RNA transcriptor.
Hungry?
The L-Two codon...
Of course.
Why didn‘t I
think of that?
Sarina...
you‘re amazing.
I‘ve been working
on this for months.
You would have seen it
sooner or later.
I don‘t know about that.
Thank you.
I‘m glad I could do
something for you.
You‘ve done so much for me.
NURSE:
Infirmary to Dr. Bashir.
Go ahead.
Dr. Girani is asking for
your assistance in surgery, sir.
I‘m on my way.
Well, looks like I‘m
going to be tied up
for the next few hours.
What would you like
to do in the meantime?
Would you like a
tour of the station?
I can ask Ezri
to show you around.
That‘s all right.
I think I‘ll go see Jack
and the others.
All right.
I‘ll have someone take
you to the cargo bay,
and when I‘m finished
with surgery
I‘ll join you there.
Oh, wait. You need
your breakfast.
Thank you.
The fact is, is that
the universe is going
to stop expanding,
and it is going
to collapse in on itself.
We‘ve got to do something
before it‘s too late.
How much time
do we have left?
60 trillion years--
70 at the most.
Oh, no!
Isn‘t Nog handsome?
What are
you doing?!
We are running
out of time!
Sarina! Thank God.
Nobody else around here
ever listens to me.
What is it, Jack?
What‘s wrong?
There‘s too much matter.
The universe is too heavy
for its own good.
You need
to lighten the load.
Yes, yes, yes, exactly.
We have to find some way
to decrease the mass.
Of the entire
universe?
That‘s the whole point.
Is that possible?
That‘s what we‘re trying
to figure out, Sarina.
What if we found a way
to manipulate subspace?
Mmm... hmm-hmm-hmm-hmm.
Change the cosmological
constant.
Mmm. Yes, yes, yes.
That‘d do the trick.
You can‘t change
the cosmological constant.
You know something,
Sarina, we are trying
to save existence
as we know it,
and all you can
do is criticize.
I‘m sorry.
Thank you!
Now, where were we?
PATRICK:
Manipulating
subspace.
JACK:
Right, right.
( sighs )
Doctor!
Glad you‘re here.
Is she all right?
Sarina, are you
all right?
She‘s fine.
Listen, you have to talk
to Starfleet for us.
We need subspace
field generators-- lots of them.
Can we talk
about it later?
Later? There isn‘t going
to be a "later" later.
JACK:
Now, once we get the
field generators...
Sarina?
Hi.
Is something wrong?
Oh, no. They‘re used
to my being quiet.
It‘s easier this way.
LAUREN:
Could be very messy.
Um... some of my friends
want to get together
a little later on
at Quark‘s,
and I was wondering
if you‘d like to come along.
Me?
Do you want to?
JACK:
When should we be ready?
Uh...
Oh, we‘re not
invited, Jack.
Just her.
Figures.
That doesn‘t
seem fair.
LAUREN:
It‘s all right.
Come on, Sarina.
Let‘s get you dressed.
LAUREN:
Sorry to keep
you waiting.
Come on out.
Come on.
Am I good,
or am I good?
Look at all the people.
Here they are.
I don‘t remember
her being so...
Beautiful.
Yeah.
Everyone,
this is Sarina.
Sarina,
this is everyone.
Odo.
Nerys.
I‘m Miles.
I remember you.
You‘re Julian‘s
best friend.
Well... we get on
all right.
For the most part.
Why are you pretending
that it‘s not true?
Because they‘re men,
and men have trouble
expressing their feelings.
You don‘t.
Oh, are you kidding?
Odo never talks
about his feelings.
He took your hand.
He‘s showing you
his feelings.
Thank you.
Julian, why don‘t
you show everybody
how much you love me
and order
the next round.
( chuckles )
Hey, Broik.
I liked your friends--
all of them.
If I had to find
someone to replace Atlas
and hold up the world,
it‘d be Miles.
He‘d do it with
a smile, too.
And Kira-- she never
doubts herself,
which is what Odo
finds so fascinating,
because he doubts
everything but her.
What about Ezri?
The day she realizes
she‘s more than just
the sum of her parts,
she‘s really going
to be something.
I can‘t believe
you saw all that
after just a few
hours with them.
I‘m going to have to start
putting on my poker face.
Too late. You‘ve already
given yourself away.
Is that right?
And how would you
describe me?
Compassionate,
brilliant,
lonely.
Well. Two out of
three isn‘t bad.
Which two?
Now, that would
be telling.
I‘m glad you
liked my friends.
I know they liked you.
I felt so comfortable
around them.
I didn‘t have to worry
that someone was going
to throw a tantrum
or break into tears
all of a sudden.
They only usually
do  that at
staff meetings.
Jack‘s always talking
about how we‘re better
than normal people.
He says that‘s why
they keep us locked up,
but he‘s wrong.
He couldn‘t get by
in the real world.
He‘d get himself
into too much trouble.
So would Lauren
and Patrick.
That‘s why they belong
in the Institute.
In fact, Doctor Loews wants
me to get them back there
as soon as possible.
I‘m not going
with them, am I?
You don‘t belong there...
not anymore.
Do they know?
Not yet.
They‘ve been like
a family to me
for as long as I
can remember.
I know how much
you care about them.
As difficult as they
can be sometimes,
I‘m going to miss them.
We had our own little world,
just the four of us.
So what‘s a genetically
enhanced girl supposed to do
when she wakes up
from a long sleep?
Point to one of those little
specks of light out there,
pack a bag and go make
a life for herself?
Why does she have to go
anywhere at all?
Sarina isn‘t going back
to the Institute with you.
She‘s not?
No, she‘s staying here.
Oh, really? Huh.
How nice for you.
I‘ve arranged for her
to have her own quarters.
We‘re never going
to see her again.
You have no right to
do this-- no right.
Look, I know you‘re
going to miss her,
but it‘s the best thing
for Sarina.
We did not help you
so you could take
her away from us.
Stop thinking about
yourself for a second,
Jack, and think about her.
Face it. She doesn‘t
belong with you anymore.
Why? Because
we‘re not normal?
Because we‘re crazy?
Oh, Jack.
Couldn‘t you make us normal
like you did for Sarina
and then we could
all stay together?
Go on, Julian.
Tell them.
There‘s nothing
you can do for us.
We‘re too far gone.
Ah, who wants to
be normal anyway?
We‘re better
than they are.
You don‘t see
any of them trying
to save the universe
from collapsing,
do you? Hmm? Hmm?
Let‘s get
back to work.
Well, they took it
rather hard.
I should go
talk to them.
In the morning.
Give them a little time
to get used to the idea.
Come on. I‘ve got just
the thing to cheer you up.
ALL:
Dabo!
O‘BRIEN:
She‘s unbelievable.
Tell them how
you do it. Go on!
It has to do with a series
of binomial equations
and probability factors.
Explain how you track
the dependent variables.
It‘s really not
that interesting.
ALL:
Dabo!
Well, hasn‘t this been fun?
Why not take a seat
and top off the evening
with a lovely bottle
of spring wine?
Should we?
He just wants you
to stop playing
so he doesn‘t lose
any more money.
Did I mention that
the wine was on the house?
Julian, let‘s
sit down.
But she‘s winning.
I‘ve... played enough.
QUARK:
This way, this way.
Uh, excuse me, excuse me.
Uh, uh, Ezri, over here.
CROWD:
Dabo!
( laughter )
( dishes clattering )
Sarina?
This way.
Julian, would you
mind if we left?
Oh, I‘m sorry.
I thought you were
having a good time.
Oh, I was, but there
was so much commotion.
Maybe I‘m just tired.
I‘ll tell you what.
Tomorrow night,
why don‘t we have
a nice, quiet dinner
in my quarters?
I have a week‘s
leave coming up.
I thought we might go
to Risa together,
get away from all
the distractions around here,
spend a little time alone.
All right.
I‘ll let you
get some rest, then.
She‘s wonderful, Miles.
I‘ve never met
anybody like her.
She‘s brilliant,
sweet...
everything‘s new to her.
Being with her
is so refreshing.
She takes such delight
in what she‘s experiencing.
It makes me appreciate
things I usually take
for granted.
Like hot coffee?
Like coffee... music...
the way the stars shine.
What is wrong with this thing?
Are you listening to me?
Yes.
Yeah.
Coffee, music, stars.
Well, don‘t you have
anything to say?
As a matter of fact,
I do, Julian.
I haven‘t seen you like this
for a long time,
and I‘m really happy for you,
but don‘t you think
it‘s all happening
just a little too fast?
Well, we‘re
genetically engineered.
We do everything fast.
Julian, she‘s your patient.
Not anymore.
I‘ve asked Doctor Girani
to take over her care.
Miles, I don‘t think
you understand
what this means to me.
All these years
I‘ve had to hide the fact
that my DNA
had been re-sequenced.
I listened to people talk about
the genetically engineered,
saying they were all misfits.
I used to fantasize
about meeting someone
who was like me,
who could live a normal life,
but it never happened--
until Sarina.
Don‘t you see?
She‘s the woman I‘ve been
waiting for all my life.
Well, good luck.
Computer...
music.
Something... romantic.
( classical music playing )
Computer, locate Sarina Douglas.
Sarina Douglas
is in her quarters
on the Habitat Ring, corridor
H-6, section 27-Epsilon.
Sarina!
It‘s me.
Computer, override door locks.
Authorization:
Bashir-delta-five-seven-alpha.
( beeping )
I‘ve been waiting
in my quarters for you.
Sarina?
Is something wrong?
Sarina.
Apparently, the thalamic
pathways I generated
are still functioning,
but Dr. Girani‘s not detected
any neural activity in them.
Do you have any idea
what‘s wrong?
Not a clue.
It‘s as if she were
just slipping away
and there‘s
nothing I can do
but wait and hope
she pulls out of it.
GIRANI:
You can go in now.
Sarina?
Don‘t be afraid.
Everything‘s going
to be all right.
I‘m not going
to give up on you... ever.
BASHIR: I don‘t know
what‘s wrong with her.
I need your help.
Why should we help you?
You just want to steal
her away from us.
Look at her!
Do you really want her
to spend the rest
of her life like this?
I mean, I‘ve been
trying to find a way
to reach her, but I can‘t.
Maybe there isn‘t one.
All I‘m asking
is that you try.
The three of
you know her
better than
anyone else.
Please... I don‘t
want to lose her.
All right, Julian.
Leave her here with us
for a while.
We‘ll see what we can do.
Thank you.
Are you sure?
I‘m sure.
We have to tell him.
Why? This way, we can
all stay together.
Let‘s go.
This way.
That way.
I think
we passed it.
Can I help you?
That‘s a stupid question.
( door chimes )
Come in.
We have to talk to you.
About Sarina?
Tell him.
She can still talk.
It‘s just that
she‘s afraid to.
I don‘t understand.
What is she afraid of?
We don‘t know.
But we think it has
something to do with you.
I‘m going to talk to her.
Stay here.
BASHIR:
Sarina.
Talk to me...
please.
I know you can.
What‘s wrong?
Is it me?
If it is, don‘t be afraid.
I‘m going to do
whatever it takes
to make it right...
because I love you.
I want us to be together.
Tell me.
Do you love me?
I don‘t know.
I don‘t even understand
what love is.
I don‘t understand
anything.
Sarina...
What am I supposed to do?
What am I supposed
to feel? Tell me.
I want to make you happy.
I owe you everything.
Shh. You don‘t owe me.
You don‘t owe me anything.
I‘m sorry.
I wish I could be the woman
you want me to be.
Shh.
Morning.
Is she gone?
Her shuttle leaves
in a few minutes.
What about the others?
They left for the Institute
this morning.
I understand you‘ve arranged
a position for Sarina
at the Corgal
Research Center.
Yeah, an internship.
She‘s going to work
under one of
the scientists there,
live with his family.
Are you okay?
How could I have been so blind?
What was I thinking,
trying to move things
along so fast?
She needed time.
I didn‘t give it to her.
I came this close
to driving her back
inside herself.
I‘m supposed to be a doctor.
I‘m supposed to put
my patient‘s needs above my own.
You didn‘t want
to be lonely anymore.
Nobody does.
( sighs )
I have to go to work.
You want to come over
for dinner tonight?
Keiko‘s making tempura.
( sighs ):
No, thanks.
So here you are...
on your way
to one of those tiny little
specks of light out there.
I guess that‘s what
a genetically enhanced girl
should do when she wakes up
from her sleep--
go make a life for herself.
I‘m going to miss you.
You won‘t forget me?
Forget you?
Never.
COMPUTER:
Final boarding call.
Well, I‘d better go.