Oh.
A little lower.
Lower.
How's that?
Well, I hope this
taught you a lesson.
What's that?
Never play springball
against a changeling.
Well, just for that
next time, I'm not going
to let you win a single game.
Well, then you'd better work
on your backhand.
Mm-mm.
Right now, all I want to do is
just sleep for two or three...
oh, oh, oh...
days.
Go right ahead.
I should be back
by the time you wake up.
Back? From where?
I received a coded message
from Gul Russol this morning.
Gul Russol.
I thought he was executed
when Cardassia
joined the Dominion.
So did I, but apparently
we were wrong.
The message says
he wants to meet with me.
Why?
I don't know
but he's my most reliable
Cardassian informant.
You mean he was.
What if Russol is dead
and this is just a trap?
I've thought about that
but I have to be sure.
I owe him that much.
Want me to come with you?
Russol insists I come alone.
Don't worry, Nerys.
I'll be careful.
Worried? Ha.
This just gives me
more time to work
on my backhand.
Chief!
How much longer
is the Promenade
going to be closed?
My bar is empty.
My waiters are bored.
And I'm losing money.
Leave me alone, Quark
or I'll feed you to one
of those plasma conductors.
Are you threatening me?
We're working as fast as we can.
As spokesman for the Promenade
Merchants' Association,
I'm going to file
an official protest
with Captain Sisko.
Put it in writing, Quark.
I'll go find a padd.
So, how much longer, Chief?
Well, we should be
through here
by the end of the day, sir.
Oh, I'm not talking
about the Promenade.
I'm talking about the Defiant.
When is the gravity net
going to be repaired?
The last time I stepped
onto the Bridge
I felt ten kilos heavier.
I'm afraid it's going
to take some time.
How much time?
About three weeks.
We have to replace
the graviton stabilizer.
You have three days.
I'm going to take the Defiant
back out on patrol
and I don't want my crew
getting queasy
because the gravity
keeps fluctuating.
But, sir, the Sector
Quartermaster said
it would take three weeks
to get us a new stabilizer.
Well, that is your problem,
Chief.
Now, I'm leaving for Bajor
for a conference
and I want
that stabilizer replaced
by the time I get back.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, sir.
I don't mean to sound negative
but I don't see
how you're going to get
the Defiant ready in three days.
Neither do I.
This Quartermaster
you've been dealing with...
what's his name?
Uh, Chief... Chief...
Chief Willoughby.
I mean his first name.
I don't know.
Is he married?
Married? What does
that have to do
with getting us
a graviton stabilizer?
Everything.
This Chief Willoughby must get
hundreds of supply requisitions
every day.
He can't possibly fill them all.
So he puts everyone
on a waiting list.
I know how he feels.
I do the same thing.
Well, the secret is
getting him to put you
at the top of that list
and the best way to do that
is to form
a relationship with him.
Get to know the name of his wife
his children.
Find out what he likes to eat.
I don't have time to form
a relationship with Willoughby.
I do.
I can get you that stabilizer,
Chief.
In three days?
Leave everything to me.
All right.
But don't do anything
I wouldn't do.
Chief, I can't operate
under those kinds
of restrictions.
At least promise me
you won't do anything
to get us court-martialed.
I'll try.
Nog!
Just kidding, Chief.
Russol?
I'm afraid he couldn't be here.
Weyoun.
Founder.
It is an honor to stand
in your presence once again.
Where's Gul Russol?
I'm afraid the Cardassian
Central Command
had him put to death
almost a year ago.
I regret having to deceive you
but it was the only way I could
think of to get you here.
Well, I'm here.
What do you want?
To serve you.
I no longer consider myself
a member of the Dominion.
You're defecting?
Do with me as you wish.
I place my fate entirely
in your hands.
You don't believe me, do you?
I believe Gul Russol is dead.
You say you're defecting
from the Dominion?
Why?
Founder, please...
I've told you before,
I'm not a Founder.
As you wish.
Odo... I'll tell you
everything you want to know
but first, we really should get
aboard your runabout.
The Jem'Hadar are
already hunting for me
and if I'm found...
You still haven't
answered my question.
Why did you decide to defect?
I realized my place is with you.
You can do better than that.
Then let's just say,
I left Cardassia
because my life was in danger.
From whom?
Everyone.
Aren't you being
a little paranoid?
Of course, I'm paranoid...
everyone's trying to kill me.
Why?
Because this war
with the Federation
was supposed to have
been won months ago.
Well, things don't always
turn out as planned.
Quite true...
and when things go wrong
someone has to take the blame
and this time, it's me.
Now...
we really should be going.
Think about it, Odo.
The information I possess
could help the Federation
win this war.
And you're willing
to share that information?
All you have to do is ask.
We've heard rumors that
the Dominion has established
a new ketracel-white
storage facility
somewhere in sector 507.
The facility's located
in the Pelosa system.
I can provide you
with the exact coordinates.
Odo to the Rio Grande,
two to beam up.
Sit here, where I can
keep an eye on you.
If it makes you feel better...
but you should know
I would never harm a God.
I'm not a God.
I'm a security officer.
As far as I'm concerned,
you're just another prisoner.
You have no idea
how much it hurts me
to hear you say that.
I spoke to Edgar.
Edgar who?
Your new best friend,
Chief Edgar Willoughby.
He wanted me to thank
you for that bottle
of Gamzian wine you sent him.
I didn't send him any wine.
I took the liberty
of sending it for you.
By the way, his wife's
name is Cynthia.
They have a daughter,
Melissa, age eight
and a son, Edgar, Jr.,
age five.
Did you get the stabilizer?
Not quite.
What do you mean, "not quite"?
Unfortunately,
he's out of stabilizers
and won't be getting
a new shipment for another week.
Oh, well, that's it;
I'm doomed.
Not necessarily.
Eddie told me the USS Sentinel
has an extra stabilizer.
What makes you think
they're going to give it to us?
I didn't say they were
going to give it to us...
but they might be willing
to trade for it.
Trade? For what?
Depends on what they need
and what we have.
Well, I suppose
it doesn't hurt to try...
but remember, be discreet.
Rule of Acquisition 168:
"Whisper your way to success."
Words to live by.
Chief, one more thing.
I need your authorization code.
What for?
The shipping orders.
Bring them to me
and I'll authorize them.
I just thought it
would save time.
When did you say the Captain
was going to be back?
Stop looking so worried, Chief.
I've got it all under control.
I sure hope so.
I wish you'd stop doing that.
Doing what?
Staring at me.
Was I?
I didn't mean to.
You've been doing it
for the last ten hours.
I'm sorry.
It's just such an honor
to be sitting here
with a G...
security officer.
We're being hailed.
Don't respond.
It's a Cardassian transmission.
Scramble the com frequencies
So they can't lock onto us.
I'm trying.
Founder...
it's an honor to speak
with you again.
You look surprised to see me,
Odo.
I'm well aware
the Vorta are all clones
but I'm not sure the universe
is ready for two Weyouns.
I couldn't agree more.
So, which of you is the Weyoun
I've had the misfortune
of dealing with
over the past few years?
Actually, neither of us.
That was Weyoun 5.
Our illustrious predecessor
was killed a month ago.
And I had the honor
of replacing him.
What a sad day that was
for the Dominion.
Weyoun 5 was a great
man, a true patriot.
His death in a transporter...
accident was most unfortunate.
And still under investigation.
A very thorough investigation
that has found
no evidence of foul play.
Interesting.
So, if you're Weyoun 6,
you must be 7.
Clones... keeping track
of them is a full-time job.
And why were you activated
if he's still alive?
Normally, I wouldn't have been
but when a clone is found
to be defective...
I'm not defective.
Of course you are.
What other explanation is there
for your behavior?
Leaving your post,
defecting to the enemy.
Are you calling Odo your enemy?
Absolutely not.
I was referring
to the Federation
as you're well aware.
Enough bickering.
Order him
to trigger his implant.
I was getting to that.
What implant?
Like all Vorta
I have a termination implant
in my brain stem.
Prove your loyalty
to the Founders...
activate it.
The only Founder
I'm loyal to is Odo
and he wants me alive.
I told you it was
a waste of time
trying to reason with him.
You're a dead man
whether you activate
the implant or not.
That ship will never make it
back to Deep Space 9.
Founder, there's
really no need for you to be
involved in this petty dispute.
If you'll just
hold your position
until one of our ships
can reach you.
I have no intention of releasing
my prisoner to you.
If you don't
I can't be responsible
for the consequences.
That's an empty threat.
He wouldn't dare harm a Founder.
Maybe he won't
but I will.
Think it over, shape-shifter.
One of our attack ships
is on the way.
Forgive me, Odo.
I should have told you
the truth about myself.
Well, it's not too late
to start.
Why did you defect?
It's quite simple really.
From the moment I was activated
I felt this war was wrong.
Please don't misunderstand me.
I still worship the Founders
but I believe their obsession
with conquering the Alpha
Quadrant is misguided.
It's time they learned
to live in peace
with the solids.
I know it's not my place
to question the Founders.
Maybe Weyoun 7 is right.
I am defective.
On the contrary.
What you're saying,
about the war
about the Founders...
makes perfect sense.
I want to thank you, Odo
for the way you stood up for me,
protected me.
Well, don't let it go
to your head.
I'd do the same
for any prisoner.
Of course, you would.
You're a God.
To think a Weyoun
could be capable
of such treachery.
I knew there was something wrong
with him from the moment we met.
He lacked your appetite
for cruelty.
He's a disgrace to me
and all Vorta.
Though... I suppose
he can't be held
completely responsible
for his behavior.
The Vorta cloning process
is a very delicate one.
Every once in a while
a clone is found
to be defective.
It's never happened
to a Weyoun before
but... it does happen.
And speaking of treachery...
there is still the little matter
of the death of Weyoun 5.
You really believe I had
something to do with that?
You were supposed
to be on that transporter pad
with him.
I was called away...
urgent meeting
with Central Command.
How convenient.
I always was lucky.
Hmm.
Are you sure I
can't interest you
in a glass of kanar?
I'm afraid our problems
won't be washed away
quite that easily.
I don't know what you're
so concerned about.
Odo couldn't possibly
hope to outrun
a Jem'Hadar attack ship.
But what if he refuses
to hand over his prisoner?
Then he'll die.
He will not.
We can't kill a Founder.
I forbid it.
Unless we stop them,
Odo is going to take
your predecessor
back to the Federation
where he will undoubtedly
reveal all he knows...
all you know...
about our strategic operations.
You know what that means,
don't you?
It means we could lose the war.
That's right.
And I will not allow that
to happen.
Cardassia has risked too much,
suffered too much.
I will not stand by
and let all of our plans
all of our dreams for
the future end in defeat
just to spare the life
of one shape-shifter.
I don't believe the Jem'Hadar
are going to fire on Odo
even if they're ordered to.
They don't need to know
he's on board.
You simply order them
to destroy the runabout.
I suppose it could work.
But if the Founders
ever found out
that we were responsible
for Odo's death...
Who's going to tell them?
Odo doesn't even consider
himself a Founder.
Then we agree.
The runabout must be destroyed.
Excellent.
Now, I really think
you should try a little kanar.
Morning, Lieutenant.
I'd make myself scarce
if I were you.
Why?
Chief.
In here now.
Tried to warn you.
Do you mind explaining this?
Where's the Captain's desk?
Oh, you don't know?
This is your authorization code,
isn't it?
Nog.
What about him?
Well, he must have traded
the Captain's desk
for the graviton stabilizer.
Excuse me?
Don't worry, Colonel.
I will get the desk back.
Oh, you're damn right, you will.
The Captain is returning
from Bajor in two days
and, when he does,
I want his desk
sitting right here,
where it belongs.
Don't worry, Chief.
I didn't give away
the Captain's desk.
I just loaned it to someone.
Who?
Al Lorenzo.
Who's Al Lorenzo?
The Chief of Operations
on Decos Prime.
What does he want
with the Captain's desk?
He wants to take
a picture of it.
Why?
He likes to collect
holophotos of himself
sitting behind the desks of
famous Starfleet Captains.
Usually, he just sneaks
into their offices
but with the war on, it's been
hard for him to get away.
Well, that makes sense.
He's got quite a collection.
Captain DeSoto's desk,
Captain Picard's...
Okay, fine.
So... once he has his picture
he's going to send us
the graviton stabilizer.
No.
He's giving us
an induction modulator.
But we don't need
But the USS Musashi does.
Ah, so the Musashi's
going to send us the stabilizer.
No. They're giving us
a phaser emitter.
But we don't need
I know,
but the USS Sentinel does
and they have
the extra stabilizer.
And they're willing to give
it up for a phaser emitter?
That's the rumor.
Rumor?
You've made all these deals
based on a rumor?
From a very reliable source.
Well, what if it turns out
not to be true?
You have to have faith, Chief.
In a rumor?
No. In the Great
Material Continuum.
Who are they?
It's not a "they."
It's the force that binds
the universe together.
I must have missed that class
in engineering school.
On Ferenginar,
we learn about the Continuum
while we still have
our first set of ears.
This is no time
for Ferengi fairy tales.
The Continuum is real.
You see, there are millions
upon millions of worlds
in the universe...
each one filled with too much
of one thing
and not enough of another.
And the Great Continuum
flows through them all
like a mighty river
from have to want
and back again.
And, if we navigate
the Continuum
with skill and grace
our ship will be filled with
everything our hearts desire.
Well, right now,
I'd settle for a stabilizer
and the Captain's desk.
The river will provide.
If it doesn't sink us first.
Odo?
Oh.
What's wrong?
I think I was...
dreaming.
Sounded more like a nightmare.
I was on Earth...
Starfleet Headquarters.
I was supposed to report
for my debriefing
but I couldn't find
the right office.
Then I started calling
your name
but you didn't answer.
And then suddenly
I was being chased
by some Jem'Hadar...
or were they Klingons?
Silly, isn't it?
Not at all.
It isn't easy to turn your back
on your own people.
Believe me, I know.
Odo, do you think Starfleet
would allow you
to conduct my debriefing?
Possibly.
It would make it much easier.
What is it?
Trouble.
I can't believe
they're firing on us.
Trust me, they are.
But the Jem'Hadar
would never obey an order
to harm a Founder.
Maybe they finally got it
through their head
that I'm not a Founder.
Or they don't know
who they're firing at.
We've got to let them know
you're on board.
They're jamming
all the frequencies.
I can't get through.
They've been ordered
not to communicate with us.
Damar said he was determined
not to let us get back
to the station.
See if you can get above them.
Why?
I'll explain later.
Just do it.
What now?
Lock phasers on their dorsal
field junction.
Their shields are weakest there.
Well, congratulations.
You've just saved our lives.
And murdered loyal servants
of the Dominion.
May the Founders forgive me.
Has it ever occurred to you
that the reason you believe
the Founders are Gods
is because that's what they want
you to believe?
That they built it in
to your genetic code?
Of course they did.
That's what Gods do.
After all, why be a God if
there's no one to worship you.
Rom, where's Nog?
I don't know, Chief.
Nog left the station
a couple of hours ago
in a runabout.
Who gave him permission
to use a runabout?
You did.
Oh! I never should have given
him my authorization code.
Did he say when he'd be back?
Not to me.
How could he do this to me?
How could he leave me adrift
mid-river without a paddle?
What river would that be?
You know, the Great
Material Continuum.
Oh, that river.
It can be very treacherous.
Tell me about it.
I suppose the good news is,
with Nog gone
nothing else can go missing.
Where are my cases
of bloodwine?!
I do not know, General
but I promise you
I will find out.
I don't understand it.
How could a runabout destroy
a Jem'Hadar fighter?
Isn't it obvious?
My predecessor must have helped
Odo get past
the ship's defenses.
Then how do we stop them?
How else?
Send more ships.
Send a whole battalion
if necessary
from our base at Olmerak.
Consider it done.
Remember to tell them
to fire on sight.
Fire at whom?
Founder, how may I serve you?
By answering my question.
We spotted a Federation
runabout spying on our base
in the Olmerak system.
Surely one ship shouldn't be
much of a threat.
We'll have it destroyed
within the hour.
Are you feeling all right?
Why do you ask?
Your face.
I'm fine
but from now on, I want
the temperature
in these rooms lowered
by 15 degrees.
I do not share
the Cardassians' love of heat.
Nor do I.
Lower the temperature.
As you wish.
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
Have you located Weyoun 6?
It's only a matter of time.
So you keep saying.
I assure you, Founder,
he will be dealt with.
Did you notice her face?
How parched it looked?
You heard her.
These rooms are too hot.
I wonder.
I'm telling you she's not well.
She's not the Founder
you should be worried about.
Contact Olmerak
and order those ships
to intercept the runabout.
Mmm... mmm-mmm.
That was filling.
I would hope so.
You've sampled
the replicator's entire menu.
I enjoyed the different...
textures.
You mean tastes, don't you?
Not at all.
The Vorta's sense of taste
is quite limited.
About the only foods
we really enjoy are
kava nuts and rippleberries.
Ah. I take it
this is also the result
of your genetic programming?
It's the Founder's way
of making sure
we remember our past.
You must know
the story of how the Founders
created the Vorta?
No.
But I have the feeling
you're going to tell me
all about it.
The Vorta used
to be quite different
from what we are today.
We were forest dwellers...
small, timid, ape-like creatures
living in hollowed-out trees.
Eating nuts and berries.
And living in fear
of the many predators
that would hunt us for food.
One day
a wounded changeling came
stumbling through the forest
fleeing from a mob
of angry solids.
Why were they chasing him?
What does it matter?
Solids have always feared
and mistrusted shape-shifters.
You know that.
Well, a family of Vorta
hid the changeling
from his pursuers
and in exchange
for saving his life
the changeling promised
the Vorta that one day
we would be transformed
into powerful beings
that we would become
an important part
of a great new empire
that would stretch
across the galaxy.
And the changeling
kept his word?
That's right.
Imagine, Odo, my people
were once little more than apes
and look at us now.
Look at what you've done for us.
If the story were true,
it would at least prove
that my people are capable
of generosity and kindness.
You care about your people
very much, don't you, Odo
in spite of all that's happened
between you?
Maybe I do,
but that doesn't change the fact
that they're responsible
for a war
that's killed millions.
Odo, there's something
you need to know.
A sickness has spread
throughout the Great Link.
The Founders...
are dying.
I was summoned to a meeting
by the female changeling.
She wanted to discuss
troop deployments with me
and suddenly,
her hands began to...
shrivel.
It lasted only a second or two
but over the last few weeks,
it's happened a number of times.
It's like she's...
withering.
And you're sure
the other changelings
are also infected?
She said the entire Link
is suffering from the disease.
Everyone but me.
If they're unable to find a cure
you'll be the last of your kind.
Why didn't you
tell me this earlier?
Because I knew
how much it would hurt you.
I'm sorry to bring you
such sad news, but at least
you're not infected.
The Dominion will survive.
Meaning what?
Think about it, Odo.
You have an opportunity
to rectify the mistakes
your people have made.
To build a new Dominion
based on cooperation,
not conquest
on peace, not war
a new order
under your leadership.
And what's your role going to be
in this "new order"?
Whatever you want it to be.
I wish only to serve you.
All right.
Then you can start
by telling me how one runabout
is going to survive an assault
by four Jem'Hadar ships.
I'm sure you'll
think of something.
There's a Kuiper belt
not far from here.
We might be able to hide
among the comet fragments.
But we don't have much time.
They're closing fast.
These comet fragments
are nothing
but huge chunks of ice.
The Jem'Hadar will have
no trouble finding us.
Not if we become the ice.
Well, with the power off
and the runabout
in thermal contact with the ice
we won't generate enough
of an energy signature
for their sensors to read.
"We become the ice."
Only a God could think
of such a thing.
Well, let's just hope
the Jem'Hadar
give up their search
before we freeze to death.
My faith will keep me warm.
Hmm. Perhaps, but in an hour
you may want to trade in that
faith for a thermal blanket.
What do you think?
It's white.
I know it's white.
I'm going to paint it.
It's the wrong shape.
It's the wrong height,
the wrong width.
Other than that, it's perfect.
The Captain'll never suspect
you switched desks on him.
Julian, I need help,
not sarcasm.
I'm afraid Nog's the only one
who can help you now.
If he gets back to the station
before the Captain does.
Maybe he's not coming back.
Maybe he's decided
to make a run for it.
That isn't the Captain's desk.
He's going to paint it.
Get it out of here!
Can I help you, General?
No... but he can!
Bloodwine?
16 cases...
sent to me by my wife.
Now, where are they?
Well, how...
how should I know?
You authorized their removal.
That is your authorization code,
is it not?
Nog.
Chief...
I want that bloodwine
back here by tomorrow.
Understood?
Odo...
when you said
you were cutting power
to all systems
did that include life-support?
I'm afraid so.
Oh. That explains it.
Explains what?
Why I'm having
trouble breathing.
We should have
enough oxygen left
for another three hours.
Of course, by then
we will have
probably frozen to death.
But you can't die.
You have to survive
to rebuild the Dominion.
They found us.
What do we do now?
We can't stay here.
You're not going to try to
outrun those ships, are you?
What choice do we have?
We're on fire.
There's an extinguisher
behind you.
What are you waiting for?
I live only to serve you.
What are you doing?
Why have you activated
the com system?
All right.
Call off those ships.
Why should I?
Because you don't
need them anymore.
I'm glad to see you've
come to your senses.
What have you done?
I've saved your life,
and the Dominion's as well.
He's activated
his termination implant
and proven himself to be
a worthy Vorta at last.
I obey the Founders
in all things.
Now call off those ships!
We don't know what he told Odo.
He may have revealed
important tactical...
It's a risk we'll
just have to take.
I've ordered the Jem'Hadar
to break off the attack.
I see your runabout
has suffered some battle damage.
Will you require
any further assistance?
I think you've done enough!
I sincerely regret
any... inconvenience
we may have caused you, Odo.
Please have a safe
and pleasant journey
back to Deep Space 9.
They say voluntary termination
is quick and painless.
I'm afraid it's not true.
I'll get you a pain suppresser.
That won't be necessary
but there is one thing
you can do for me.
What's that?
Give me your blessing.
I... I can't.
Please, Odo.
Tell me I haven't failed;
that I've served you well.
You have, and for that
you have my gratitude...
and... my blessing.
Miles, the Captain's back.
I know.
He sent for me.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Ah, Chief.
Captain, your desk...
Yes, it looks nice,
doesn't it?
I came in this morning and found
Ensign Nog polishing it.
It was looking a little dull.
Well, here is
the maintenance request
from the Gettysburg.
It should be docking
here later today.
That'll be all.
Yes, sir.
Oh, about the stabilizer...
Captain, I-I can explain.
Don't bother.
Ensign Nog tells me
you were able to get
ahold of one this morning.
I was?
I mean, I was.
How long before
you can have it on line?
Um... eight hours.
I plan to take the Defiant
out on patrol in two.
Two it is, sir.
I don't know
how you did it, Nog.
I never lost faith
in the Great Material Continuum.
Ah, like you say
the River will provide.
Chief!
The waters
just got choppy again.
I want you to have this.
Consider it an apology.
Well... you found
the bloodwine?
Not exactly.
Ensign Nog returned from
his trip with 16 cases
of 2309...
a very good year.
An even better vintage
than the one my wife sent me.
Well, I'm, uh...
I'm glad you approve.
And remember
any time you're shopping
for wines or spirits
my Cousin Gant
is the man to see.
We will keep that in mind.
Your Cousin Gant?
Just another sailor
on the Great River.
Ah...
By the way, Gant mentioned
he's got ten cases
of Saurian brandy.
It's the Captain's
favorite, you know.
Level 5.
What does he want for them?
I don't think I'll ever forget
the look on his face
when he died.
He seemed so...
content.
The last thing he saw
was one of his Gods
smiling at him.
If you ask me,
he was a lucky man.
Nerys, please.
No, listen to me.
I know to Starfleet
the Prophets are nothing more
than wormhole aliens
but to me, they're Gods.
I can't prove it.
Then, again, I don't have to
because my faith
in them is enough
just as Weyoun's faith in you...
was enough for him.
Well, now it appears
that the Vorta
may have to learn
to get along without their Gods.
I'm sorry.
You're worried
about your people.
The changelings are dying,
and I can't help them.
They're the enemy.
A very dangerous enemy.
Now more than ever
because they're
all so desperate.
This isn't easy for you
but you have to remember
they started this war.
You didn't.
That's true...
but I know now
whichever side wins,
one thing is certain...
I'm going to lose.