Come on. Santa Anna didn't care
about the rules of war.
If he had executed
Davy Crockett at the Alamo
he would have considered it
a point of pride.
All right, put
it this way--
in 1836, Davy Crockett
was what, 49?
Quite old
for the standards of the time.
His days as an Indian fighter
were well behind him.
He was just an ex-Congressman--
all reputation.
Now, this is not a man
who was about to fight
till his last breath, Miles.
The situation was hopeless.
He was out of ammunition.
The Mexican army was storming
the Alamo's battlements.
He would have surrendered.
It's as logical
as that-- simple.
I'm not saying
it couldn't have happened.
I'm just saying
there's no proof.
WORF:
You are
both wrong.
The only real question
is whether you believe
in the legend
of Davy Crockett or not.
If you do, then there should be
no doubt
in your mind
that he died
a hero's death.
If you do not believe
in the legend
then he was just a man
and it does not matter
how he died.
Well, I guess
that settles that.
I guess so.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Kor...
Nuq'nuh, Worf.
It's good to see you,
my friend.
I welcome you to my home.
May I offer you
some refreshment?
I would be honored to share
a bottle of bloodwine
with the son of Mogh.
I heard the news about Jadzia.
She died a warrior.
I expected
nothing less.
To absent comrades.
Mmm! 2309.
Very good.
Sit.
Oh.
The war goes, um,
well for you, Worf?
Um, a long list of victories
to your credit, I trust?
I have been... fortunate.
Oh-ho-ho, the way of the warrior
is not a humble path.
Show some pride
in your accomplishments.
You've earned it.
I will try.
( chuckles )
And does the war go well
for you, Kor?
No, Worf,
it does not go well for me.
It seems
my... services
are not required
in the present conflict.
But you are Kor--
a Dahar Master
the man who held
the Korma Pass
against T'nag.
Your reputation alone should
have assured you a command.
I also have a reputation
for a certain ruthless quality
towards those who
would stand in my way.
Mind you,
it's not entirely undeserved.
In truth, I rather enjoy being
feared by my fellow officers.
However, there's a price
to be paid for such...
single-minded devotion
to one's ambition.
I've made enemies...
perhaps
more than were necessary.
I have no influence left
in the Empire.
Even as our
entire race
grapples with
the Dominion
there's no place
for an old man
with too many enemies
and not enough friends.
That's why
I've come here tonight.
It's not easy
for me to beg you for help...
but I have nowhere else to turn.
Help me fight again, Worf.
Help me end my life
as I've lived it--
as a warrior.
How many more reports
does the High Council require?
As many as last time.
And Starfleet is still
waiting for your signature
on these repair requests.
( groans )
There will come a day, Darok
when your services as my aide
will no longer be required.
I look forward to that day
with great anticipation.
Until then...
( hatch opening )
Ah, Worf!
Good to see you.
Thank you, Darok.
It's a pity
Captain Sisko
frowns on summary executions.
What can I do for you?
Kor, the Dahar Master
came to see me
last night.
He has been unable
to find a command and I...
Tell me you're
not going
to ask me
to give that man a ship.
Well, I had hoped...
Then your hopes are in vain.
That man is not welcome
in my House
and I will certainly
not have him
commanding a ship in my fleet.
General, Kor is a friend,
and I have already...
Not another word!
Do you hear?
Not one word!
Now get out of here
before I forget we are brothers.
MARTOK:
I plan to attack
the Trelka V Starbase
then push deeper
into Cardassian territory.
I'll hit the Manora shipyards
the Jem'Hadar breeding
facility on Sheva II
the supply depots
in the Borias Cluster.
It would take half
the Ninth Fleet
just to destroy Trelka V.
I don't intend to destroy
the base, just damage it--
throw them off-balance
then move on
to the next target.
Imagine... the chaos we'll cause
once we're in
behind their lines.
A cavalry raid.
Ancient Earth soldiers
mounted on horseback.
They had the speed
to charge behind enemy lines
to stir up trouble
and the mobility
to keep from being caught.
How many ships will you take?
Five birds-of-prey.
Battle cruisers are too slow
too unwieldy
for a mission like this.
Do you want to take
the Defiant?
Perhaps the Defiant
should remain here
just in case the Jem'Hadar try
their own "cavalry raid," hmm?
But it may be prudent
for the Defiant
and a dozen or so
other starships
to be waiting for us
when we return.
You mean you might be bringing
company back with you?
I'm sure you'll be
ready to welcome them.
With phasers charged.
( chuckles )
( both laughing )
Our disruptor targeting sensors
need to be replaced
as well as our
guidance system relays.
Make a note of that
for Chief O'Brien.
He should give the Ch'Tang
first priority.
So, if you have something
to ask me, do it now
before Darok buries me
under more paperwork.
I wish to speak
with you about Kor.
Now, I know you have
strong feelings about...
Clear the Bridge!
I did not expect
to hear anything
further on this
subject from you.
And I did not expect
to be forbidden
to speak with you
on any subject.
Have I become a shuVak
to be ordered about
like Darok?
No.
Of course not.
Very well.
Talk and be
done with it.
Kor came to see me,
asking my help as a friend.
He is an old man
with no family and no influence
left in the Empire.
He asked nothing
except for the chance
to fight and die
as a Klingon warrior.
I told him I would
speak with you
about finding him
a command in the fleet.
I would not give that man
the gnawed bones of my last meal
much less command of a ship.
But why?
There is no blood feud
between our Houses
and Kor has said
he has not even met you.
You can wound a man
without ever seeing his face.
( stamps foot )
When I was a boy,
my family still lived
in the lowlands
of Ketha Province.
We had very little,
but it didn't matter.
We were a family of warriors.
15 generations had served
as soldiers of the Empire
but my father had
higher hopes for me.
He wanted his son
to become an officer.
( chuckles ):
It took a great deal of effort
but eventually, he found someone
willing to sponsor me.
I passed my entrance exam
on my first attempt
and all that remained
was final approval
by the Oversight Council--
a simple formality.
My application was rejected
by one member
of that council-- Kor.
Why?
"Why?"
Kor's family descends
from the Imperial Court itself.
Kor is "of the blood"--
born to rule
by the divine will of Kahless
and what was I?
A boy from the
Ketha lowlands.
He could not bear the thought
of someone like me joining
the elite officer ranks
and so, to my father's
embarrassment
and my everlasting shame...
my application was denied.
And with the mark
of Kor on my record
I could not join
even as a common soldier.
I spent five years
as a civilian laborer
aboard General
ShiVang's flagship.
Then... as fortune
would have it
the Romulans made a foolhardy
attempt to board our ship.
I earned
a battlefield commission.
Unfortunately...
my father did not live
to see that glorious day.
And if Kor had had his way
I would still be
a civilian on that ship
cleaning
the officers' mess.
I understand
but I must tell you
that using my own authority
I appointed Kor
an officer in the Ninth Fleet.
Made him an officer...
just like that.
That's the difference
between his name and mine--
his opens doors,
mine closes them.
I did not anticipate...
It's done!
Your apology is not sought
but know this, Worf...
Kor is your responsibility.
I want nothing
to do with him.
Do you...
do you remember
breaking into
the Duke's harem on Renavi?
Oh.
How could I
forget that?
That is one of Curzon's
favorite memories.
( Ezri and Kor laughing )
Hi.
Hello.
KOR:
Come and join us
my friend.
Uh... I am on duty.
I'll see you later.
Mmm.
It's good to see
you again, Kor.
Mm-hmm.
Still the same old Dax...
and yet not.
General Martok will not
give you a command.
Uh... kesh!
He says that
you struck his name
from an officers list
because his family comes
from the Ketha lowlands.
Did I?
I don't recall.
Of course, there were
so many officer lists.
I suppose it's possible.
It is an unworthy reason to bar
a man from serving the Empire.
Worf, you've been living
among this democratic rabble
for too long.
I know your bloodline.
We both come from noble Houses.
Among our people,
that still counts for something.
If Martok
is a true Klingon
he should
appreciate that.
He does not.
( snorts in disdain )
Did he revoke my commission?
No. You will serve
aboard the Ch'Tang...
as Third Officer.
Third?
( scoffing )
( sigh of resignation )
Oh, well... huh, no matter.
I've overcome greater obstacles.
Thank you, Worf.
You're a true friend.
You will report aboard at 0700
and stay out of Martok's way.
He will not even know
I am there.
Worf!
Uh... what was the
name of that ship?
Oh, the Ch'Tang.
Ch'Tang! Of course.
I'll see you there.
OFFICER:
All decks report ready.
Defense systems on-line.
Engine room standing by.
Transporter room reports
that our last crew members
have beamed aboard.
Very well.
Signal the squadron.
Prepare to
get under way.
Stand by to cloak.
Aye, sir.
Helm, set course 325 mark 003.
Full impulse till we
clear the outer marker.
Then go to...
Third Officer Kor
reporting for duty.
The Dahar Master.
( soft growling )
Take your station.
MARTOK:
Return to your duties
or I will find a crew that can.
Helmsman
I gave you
an order.
chaH-Veh!
Kor...
here on our ship.
( laughing )
Don't you have
something to do?
No.
Then find something!
It's an honor to have you
aboard with us.
Ah, thank you very much.
Welcome, Dahar Master.
So what did Kor say
when he met you?
The usual.
I have the same conversation
over and over again.
Everyone's
shocked at first.
Then they start
scanning my face
for signs of the person
they knew as Dax.
"It can't be.
"Is it really you?
"Oh, I do see
a little Jadzia in the eyes
a little Curzon
in the smile."
Isn't there a period
of adjustment
that joined Trills
have to go through
where people
are comparing them
to previous hosts?
I'm, I'm sure it'll pass.
You're right.
The last five Dax hosts
went through this.
Ah.
That wasn't bad.
You'd make a pretty
good Counselor.
You want to trade jobs?
Oh, yeah-- people
would love
bringing their
problems to me.
"You dreamt about what?
"You're crazy.
"Now get out
of my office.
Next patient."
It's funny you should
mention dreams.
Ever since
my conversation with Kor
I have had the most
intense dreams about him.
Like what?
Being on a Klingon
Bridge together...
going off
into battle...
drinking bloodwine--
which still makes me gag
by the way.
Singing songs...
A part of me wants to be
out there with him now.
I hope he's
all right.
I mean, I know I'm sort
of contradicting
what I just said
about wanting
to set myself apart
from my previous hosts
but the memories I have
of being with him
are so vivid.
I can't bear the
thought of losing him.
I'd give almost anything
for the chance to...
be together just one more time--
the two of us side by side,
just like it used to be.
Do you need something?
No.
Nothing.
So, what's your
professional opinion?
Mmm... you're crazy.
Next patient.
What's the matter
with you?
Someone forget
to leave a tip?
It's Ezri.
She... she...
I can't even say it.
Try.
She wants to get back
together with Worf.
And before the Cardassians
ever knew we were there
we destroyed the entire camp
and the relay station.
( all laughing )
To General Martok--
victor of Felton Prime.
( soft growl )
ALL:
Qapla'!
OFFICER:
Let me have the honor
to welcome
the Dahar Master
to the humble mess hall
of the Ch'Tang.
Oh, sit, sit.
You do me too much honor.
On this voyage,
I am but the Third Officer.
I expect no special treatment.
OFFICER:
May I serve you gagh,
Dahar Master?
Have you settled on
an attack plan
for the starbase
on Trelka V?
I'm going to send
the Malpara and the Ning'tao
in ahead of the rest
of the squadron.
They'll make
a single strafing run
of the base
then head out
of the system.
When the enemy sends out
their repair crews
to assess the damage,
then the rest
of the squadron
will de-cloak.
With any luck, we'll catch
them not only unprepared
but with their entire damage
control effort under way.
Excellent.
An excellent plan, General.
I'm glad you approve.
KOR:
Of course.
It's the same tactic
Kang and I used
against the Federation
in the Battle of Caleb IV.
You were at
Caleb IV?
Of course
he was.
Forgive the
ignorance of
these children.
( chuckling )
I was a young officer once.
I know how irrelevant
the past can seem.
We would be honored
if you would tell us
about Caleb IV.
( all agreeing )
DAROK:
Tell the tale.
OFFICER:
Tell us.
KOR:
Well, there's not much
to tell, really.
The battle was over
almost before the Federation
knew it had begun.
I commanded the First Division
from the Klothos--
one of the old D-5 cruisers.
Kang commanded
the Second Division.
Now, you must remember
that in those days
the cloaking device was
a new piece of technology.
( laughing )
There were only
a handful of engineers
in the Imperial Fleet
who knew how to operate them.
Before we left Chronos
I spent three days
in the Engine Room
taking the
device apart
with my bare hands...
( clanking )
and then putting it
back together again.
Now, this would
come in handy
later in the battle,
as you'll see.
It is not the fault
of the crew.
They are not
used to serving
with a legendary
figure like Kor.
OFFICER ( on com ):
Bridge to General Martok.
Yes.
OFFICER:
We are approaching Trelka V.
Set defense condition one.
( warning signal blares )
OFFICER:
Defense condition one.
All hands to battle stations.
Repeat, all hands
to battle stations.
( warning signal continues )
I'm supposed to be somewhere.
Dahar Master?
Where are you going,
Lieutenant?
To, to the Bridge.
We're approaching
Trelka V.
The Bridge!
Are you all right?
Of course.
What are you waiting for?
Report to your station.
chaH-Veh!
Concentrate!
OFFICER:
Their shields are
down to 65 percent.
Three Cardassian cruisers
are in spacedock
orbiting on the far
side of the planet.
Two of them are
getting under way.
The Malpara
and the Ning'tao
have completed their attack.
The Malpara is gone...
No survivors.
The Ning'tao is heading
out of the system.
The Cardassians
are pursuing.
MARTOK:
And leaving
their base
unprotected.
Helm, take us in.
Bring us
to a hover
300 meters
above the base.
Stand by
to de-cloak
on my command.
Holding at 300 meters.
Scan the base.
They've dispatched
damage control teams.
Two defense batteries are out.
And they've just dropped
their primary shield grid.
De-cloak the ship
and open fire.
( groaning )
Shields are down to 85 percent.
( yells )
Reroute emergency power
to secondary
shield emitters.
Fire torpedoes!
Helm, lay in an escape course.
( yells )
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
KOR:
Continue firing.
Target their primary reactors.
chaH-Veh.
And bring us around
for another pass.
Coming about.
( weakly ):
No... only one pass.
Leave the system.
Do not worry, my friend.
All is well.
You old... fool!
OFFICER:
The Orantho reports
their Captain
and First Officer are dead.
They have a hull breach
in their port quarter.
Instruct them to continue firing
and open a
channel to Kang.
To Kang?
Tell him we've succeeded
and that the Federation
outpost on Caleb IV
will be taken within an hour.
Sir, Kang has been dead
for years.
Prepare a boarding party.
We're going to take the base.
But, sir, they have
a garrison of 10,000.
By the hand of Kahless,
get us out of here!
Victory is ours.
The Federation
will rue the day
they dared to challenge
the might of the Klingon Empire.
We will take
Caleb IV
and raise
our banner
over the smoking ruins
of their outpost.
Escape course, now!
MARTOK:
Engage cloaks.
( groaning )
Orantho and
Slivin have cloaked.
No pursuit from Trelka V.
No time to waste.
Proceed... proceed
to the rendezvous
and then on to the
Manora shipyards.
Warp 7.
Medical team
to the Bridge.
Worf, get that man out of here.
Hi. I think I'm in
the mood for a...
Wait.
I have something to say.
Now, you may think
this is none of my business
but someone has
to speak up
and I've decided
that someone is me.
So, here it is.
I'll just say it.
Okay.
You're making a mistake
by pursuing another
relationship with Worf.
Excuse me?
You heard me.
I know how Jadzia
felt about Worf
but that was her life,
not yours.
You're Ezri Dax.
You need
to give yourself
a chance to explore
other relationships.
You're young... and beautiful
and full of life.
Why go after a man
who's only a memory to you?
I've had my problems
with Worf, I'll admit that
but this is not about
me or my feelings.
This is about you.
Worf has done nothing,
and I mean nothing
to deserve you.
Shouldn't you try
and find someone
who's willing
to win your heart
not just inherit it?
You deserve better.
There.
I've said my piece.
Can I say something now?
I'm not interested in having
another relationship with Worf.
I care about him
and I probably always will,
but he's moved on with his life
and so have I.
Oh. Well, good.
And I'd also like to say
that what you just did
was one of the kindest,
dearest, and for you
one of the most
embarrassing things
that I have
ever heard.
You're a real
sweetheart.
Can I order now?
Mm-hmm.
A Moscow mule.
Coming right up.
Did you hear that?
She called me "sweetheart."
Yeah? So?
She loves me.
What?
"Sweetheart."
You're certifiable,
you do realize that?
She loves me.
( sighs )
( door opens )
MARTOK:
Find out what's wrong
with the Ning'tao.
I know Captain Lurkan is young
but he must realize
the importance...
the importance
of keeping formation.
I've been thinking
about our next objective.
Perhaps we should
go after a bigger target
something more threatening
to our forces.
Now, what about the base
on Caleb IV?
( Officer chuckles )
DAROK:
If you'll excuse me,
I have duties
to attend to.
Your duties are right here.
Someone was just telling me
about the defenses
on Caleb IV.
Who was that?
OFFICER:
I believe it was
our Third
Officer, General.
That's right.
Third Officer.
Tell us about Caleb IV.
Is it manned by Jem'Hadar
or Cardassian troops?
I thought it was
a Federation outpost.
How can that be?
The Federation
is our ally.
Surely Kor is
aware of that.
Perhaps he's confused.
Confused? The
Dahar Master?
Surely not.
We must be the ones
who are confused.
Enlighten us.
Who mans the base
on Caleb IV--
Dominion or Federation?
I think he's forgotten.
I think he's asleep.
MARTOK:
Stop it!
Both of you.
Don't you have
any respect
for one of the greatest
heroes of the Empire?
He's thinking it over.
Give him time.
The last son of the House
of Kor should not be rushed.
How long should we wait?
Perhaps we
should ask Kang!
Well, say something, old man
or have you lost your tongue
as well as your mind?
Savor the fruit of life,
my young friends.
It has a sweet taste
when it is fresh from the vine
but don't live too long.
The taste turns bitter...
after a time.
The new personnel roster.
You've removed Kor
from active duty.
I saw no other choice.
Still, you're his friend.
It must have been
difficult for you.
A friend would not
have put him
in that position
in the first place.
I've hated his name
for almost 30 years.
I've dreamt of the moment
when I would finally see him
stripped of his rank and title
when he would
suddenly find himself
without a friend
in the world
without the power
of his birthright.
Well, I've had
that moment now.
And I took no joy from it.
Have you thought about
what will become of him
when we return
to Deep Space 9?
I plan to speak with
Chancellor Gowron
to try and find Kor some
assignment on the Homeworld.
I'll have a word
with Gowron as well.
Bridge to General Martok.
Yes?
Pardon the interruption, sir.
Our sensors have detected
a large body of enemy ships.
On my way.
( warning signal blares )
Where are they?
Their warp signatures
are bearing directly astern.
They're Jem'Hadar fighters
and they appear
to be pursuing us.
How can that be?
The lead ship
is using some sort
of long-range
tachyon scanner
to penetrate our cloaks.
Does the Dominion possess
such a device?
They do now.
How many ships?
I've identified
ten vessels so far.
( sighs ):
And they're gaining on us.
WORF:
How long before
we are within their
weapons' range?
Two hours, 12 minutes.
Helm... have you located
the Defiant?
Yes, sir. They're
waiting for us
in the Kalandra Sector with
seven Federation starships.
It will take us...
three hours, 45 minutes
to reach them.
If the Jem'Hadar could be forced
to drop out of warp
for only ten minutes
they would not have time
to catch up with us
before we rendezvous
with the Defiant.
It's a fine theory,
but how do we execute it?
We could disrupt
their warp fields
with an inverse
graviton burst.
It would force them
to drop to impulse
until the gravitons
dissipated.
We would need to generate
a massive burst
to disrupt the warp fields
of a fleet that size.
A single bird-of-prey
could do it by diverting
warp power to the
main deflector.
How long would that delay them?
They could
reinitialize their warp cores
in less than two minutes.
If I could engage
them in battle
while they are
still at impulse
that would delay
them even longer.
I know I could do it.
What do you mean,
you could do it?
The Orantho's Captain
and First Officer are dead
and the Slivin's
deflector is damaged
and cannot generate
a graviton burst...
and the Ning'tao's Captain
is too young and inexperienced.
I am the logical choice.
But, Worf...
this means that
you'd be sacrificing
the... entire crew
of the Ning'tao.
I have thought
about that.
We could beam most
of the crew over
before I take command.
I would only need
six volunteers.
Signal the Ning'tao.
Tell them to prepare
for a change in command.
( door chimes )
Yes?
I'm not hungry.
The food is for me.
I haven't eaten in hours.
Men of our generation
never stood on
ceremony, huh?
( laughing )
We ate when we
were hungry.
We fought when
we were angered.
Oh... I miss
the simplicity
of those days.
I miss a great deal
about those days.
The warriors
on this ship...
they don't know
what they've missed
but such is the
way with children.
Hmm?
They often let the
promise of the future
obscure the glories
of the past.
Is there a point
to this nostalgic indulgence?
Only that they
are children.
Even Martok, who,
for all his flaws,
is a great man
even Martok is but
a child compared
to you or me.
They are quick to judge,
but slow to forgive.
They still have
much to learn.
We are being pursued
by a Jem'Hadar fleet.
Worf believes he can stop them
with a single ship.
How?
It's a good plan...
but it has one flaw.
It depends entirely
on Worf successfully
engaging the whole
enemy fleet
if only for a short time.
It can be done.
The key is to confuse
their sensors
in the opening moments...
with a spread of torpedoes.
Perhaps.
But it would take a man
with three times his experience
to accomplish
such a feat
and such a man... would have
to be certain of his abilities.
Such a man
would not take the job...
unless he were certain.
It has been an honor serving
with you, Kor, son of Rynar.
Worf!
Leaving for
the Ning'tao,
I take it?
Yes.
I wanted to
wish you well.
I look forward
to seeing you
at the gates
to Sto-Vo-Kor.
As do I.
Do you have any message
you want me to convey
to Jadzia?
( grunts )
When I reach the Halls
of the Hallowed Dead
I will find your beloved
and remind her that her husband
is a noble warrior
and that he still loves
no one but her.
Good-bye, my friend.
Live well.
Long live the Empire.
On the Bridge?
If they succeed, you can
drink to their courage...
and if they fail
you can still drink
to their courage.
The Ning'tao
is closing on the enemy.
She's initiated
the graviton burst.
Their warp fields
are destabilizing.
They're dropping to impulse.
By Kahless' hand... how many?
All of them.
The Ning'tao has
dropped out of warp.
She's engaging
the enemy.
Die well, Worf.
Today was not
my day to die.
Worf!
But then who...?
Kor!
He surprised me
outside the transporter room
with a hypospray.
I hope that old fool
understands what he's doing.
How goes the battle?
We're approaching the limit
of our sensor range...
but it appears that the enemy
formation has collapsed.
The Ning'tao is
maneuvering rapidly.
She's taking heavy fire
from the Jem'Hadar.
I've lost contact.
One ship... against ten...
it doesn't seem possible.
He will succeed.
He is Kor--
the Dahar Master.
He's done it.
The Jem'Hadar
are out of time.
They can no longer overtake us
before we reach the Defiant.
How... how did that
pompous old man
hold off an entire
Jem'Hadar fleet
with only one ship?
Does it matter?
Darok, give me that bottle.
To Kor...
the Dahar Master...
a noble warrior
to the end.
My-cho Qara, end-do keela
bay-doH chum,
ka ree-do meela
ALL:
Stum-pa rip-to
Maah-la ee'qo
ree-kaH!
ree-kaH! ree-kaH!
Maah, so faH ka'lee
te cho-paH...