One, two, three, four, one.
She likes the free, fresh
Wind in her hair
Life without care
She's broke, but it's oke
Hates California
It's cold and it's damp
That's why the lady
That's why
the lady
That's why the lady
Is a scamp.
Ha...
So, what do you think?
Not bad.
But the lady is a "tramp"
not a scamp.
Tramp, right.
So, do I get the..."gig"?
Sorry, pally.
But Dr. Bashir said you're
looking for an opening act
and I love to sing.
I can tell, but two singers
on the same bill...
that's a one-way ticket
to Deadsville.
I need someone to warm
up the audience for me.
You know, a comic.
A comic?
A comedian.
Someone who can make
people laugh.
I can do that...
my brother tells me
people are always
laughing at me.
Well, that may be true
but this is a holosuite program,
capisce?
So?
So, you're not a hologram.
Life can be so unfair.
Vic, you got a minute?
Forget it.
He's not hiring.
What's wrong with him?
Show biz.
It can break your heart.
So, what can I do for you,
pally?
Uh, did you get
a chance to make
those audio recordings for me?
All your favorite hits.
That's great.
Thanks, Vic.
My pleasure.
These songs are 400 years old.
You sure the troops
on the front lines
want to hear them?
Well, the songs may be old
but when you sing them,
they sound brand new.
Hey, when you put it that way
I wish I was going
on the supply run with you.
I could make some
personal appearances.
Sing a few songs,
tell a few jokes.
You know, put on
a regular USO show.
I'm afraid
there are no holosuites
where we're going.
Rom's right.
Life can be unfair.
You know, pally
sometimes being a hologram
can be a real pain
in the asometric photons.
I'll see you when I get back.
Well, you know where to find me.
I thought I might find you here.
The new security protocols
you requested.
I think that's what I'm going
to remember most
about this war...
looking through
casualty reports.
Sometimes it feels like
that's all I do...
stare at the names
of the dead.
When the war started,
I read every name.
I felt it was the
least I could do
to honor their sacrifices.
But now...
the names have begun
to blur together.
Well, that's understandable.
Maybe.
Ops to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
The Defiant is ready
for departure.
On my way.
Why me?
Why did he have to send me?
I'm like a son to him.
Quark, you're mumbling again.
I'm sorry.
It's...
it's just not fair.
I have responsibilities
of my own
customers who depend on me.
But the Grand Nagus picked you
for this assignment.
Some assignment...
a fact-finding mission
to the front lines.
Zek's already inundated with
Starfleet Intelligence reports.
What could I tell him
that he doesn't know?
Maybe he wants to hear things
from a Ferengi perspective.
Then let him ask Nog.
The Nagus trusts you.
What are you trying to do?
Cheer me up?
It's my job.
Remember the 34th Rule
of Acquisition.
"War is good for business."
Only from a distance.
The closer you are
to the front lines
the less profitable it gets.
What is that?
Stay here.
Wait! Don't leave!
This is no time
to be wandering the corridors.
I thought the Chin'toka System
was in Federation hands.
It is, but the Dominion
is determined
to take back their territory.
The whole system's
a battleground.
Thank you.
I should probably
write this down.
Mr. O'Brien, keep an eye out
for more Jem'Hadar ships.
Aye, sir.
What are you doing here, Uncle?
I'm... visiting.
I'm working.
Quark, is there something
we can do for you?
Not really.
I just came by to say
hello to my nephew.
All right.
You've just said hello.
Anybody here who would
like to join me
in the mess hall
for a raktajino?
Quark.
I'm just leaving.
Sir, I assure you
that won't happen again.
Nog, your uncle's just
a little nervous.
He's not used to being
in a combat situation.
That's no excuse.
Captain, the supplies
are ready for transport.
AR-558 has acknowledged
your message.
They are expecting you.
Away team, you're with me.
Mr. Worf, she's all yours.
Aye, sir.
Not much to look at, is it?
Those are Federation phasers.
Hold your fire!
I'm Captain Benjamin Sisko
of the USS Defiant.
You heard him!
Cease fire, damn it!
We're coming out!
Who told you to open fire?
I saw movement.
I thought it was the Jem'Hadar.
They look like Jem'Hadar to you?
I gave the word
to hold your fire;
that Starfleet Officers
were beaming down with supplies.
Well, nobody told me.
Sorry, Captain...
a little breakdown
in communications.
No harm was done.
Where's Captain Loomis?
He was killed ten days ago.
So was Commander Parker.
Who's in command?
I am.
Lieutenant Nadia Larkin.
Ben Sisko.
Where do you want
your supplies?
Vargas can show you.
Supplies... that's great.
Don't they know we need
to get off this rock?
Take it easy, Vargas.
Take it easy?
I would love to take it easy.
Get me out of this vole hole
and I promise you
for the rest of my life
all I'll do is
just take it easy.
According
to Starfleet regulations
we're supposed to be rotated
off the front lines
after 90 days. 90 days.
We've been stuck
on this rock
for five months, Captain.
Take it easy.
Welcome to paradise, Captain.
There it is...
the only reason
anyone gives a damn
about this place.
It's the largest Dominion
communications array
in the sector.
If we can figure
out how it works
we should be able to tap
into their entire com system.
One thing's for sure...
they're determined
to get it back.
We can't let that happen.
I know our orders, Captain
but maybe Starfleet Command
isn't aware of our situation.
We've been holding this place
for five months...
that's five months
of fighting off
repeated Jem'Hadar
attempts to get it back.
When we landed here,
there were 150 of us.
We're down to 43.
I appreciate
what you've gone through
and I will make sure
that Starfleet understands
your situation
but from what I hear
our forces are spread
pretty thin in this system.
Chances are,
you're going to be stuck here
for a while longer.
Lucky us.
Can someone hand me
a duonetic coupler?
Thanks.
Your frequency
discriminator seems
to be drifting.
You might want to reset it.
You an engineer?
No... but Tobin,
one of my previous hosts, was.
Close enough.
Pick up a microdyne coupler
and start recalibrating
that transtator.
Nog, shouldn't you be
helping Dr. Bashir
unload the supplies?
We're pretty much finished.
Good.
The sooner we get
out of here, the better.
That soldier over there,
you see his necklace?
Those are ketracel-white tubes.
So?
You know how he got them?
Mail order?
He took them off the bodies
of dead Jem'Hadar...
Jem'Hadar that he killed.
It's his way of keeping score.
And you find that impressive?
Isn't it?
I don't think so.
Take a look around you, Nog.
This isn't
the Starfleet you know.
Sure it is.
It's just that these people
have been through a lot.
They've been holed up here
a long time...
seen two-thirds
of their unit killed
but they haven't surrendered...
and do you know why?
Because they're heroes.
Maybe, but I still
don't want you
anywhere near them.
Let me tell you something
about hu-mans, Nephew.
They're a wonderful,
friendly people
as long
as their bellies are full
and their holosuites
are working...
but take away
their creature comforts
deprive them of food,
sleep, sonic showers...
put their lives in jeopardy
over an extended period of time
and those same, friendly,
intelligent, wonderful people
will become as nasty
and as violent
as the most
bloodthirsty Klingon.
You don't believe me?
Look at those faces.
Look in their eyes.
You know I'm right, don't you?
Well...
aren't you going
to say something?
I feel sorry for the Jem'Hadar.
This is 20cc's
of numinol tetraminothen.
That'll take care of the fever
and the chest congestion.
This... will get rid
of the dermal irritation
on your back.
Better?
Oh... are you kidding?
I haven't felt this good
since the day I landed
on this rock.
Good. Now, I'd like
to take a look at this arm.
What the hell are you doing?
You keep your hands
off this bandage.
I need to treat your wound.
Nobody touches this bandage.
Is that understood?
Why is that?
I asked you if you understood.
Yes.
McGreevey
put this bandage on me.
He ripped up his own uniform
to make it.
He sounds like a good friend.
He was a jerk.
I couldn't stand the guy.
He wouldn't shut up.
Yap, yap, yap.
He thought he was
the world's greatest authority
on everything.
I know... he's dead,
and I should have more respect
but God, I hated him.
One minute, he's tying
this bandage around my arm
talking his head off
and the next minute,
he's lying flat on his back
with a hole in his chest...
and I just sat there
and I looked at him.
It was so great.
He was so quiet!
One time in his life,
he's quiet!
I still need
to treat your wound.
I think you've set up
a solid defense perimeter
but you need
to tighten this flank.
Captain, can I have a minute?
These people's physical
and mental health
is precarious at best.
They need more than
a few food replicators
and medical supplies.
They need to be
shipped out of here.
I understand that, but right now
there's nothing I can do
about that.
Damn it!
I saw it happen.
He was walking along...
You must have swept the compound
for antipersonnel mines.
A hundred times.
It doesn't help,
not with Houdinis.
Houdinis?
Find one and you disappear.
They hide in subspace
and appear at random.
You can walk by the same
place a hundred times
and nothing happens,
and then, bang.
You're wasting
your breath, Vargas.
It's not the Captain's problem.
He's leaving.
I wish I could tell you
things were going
to get easier for you.
Don't worry about us,
Captain.
Defiant to Captain Sisko.
Go ahead.
Sir, we're being attacked
by two Jem'Hadar ships.
We have locked
onto your coordinates.
Are you ready for transport?
Stand by, Mr. Worf.
Captain, sensors
show Jem'Hadar troops landing
nine kilometers
from your position.
Sir, we must
beam you aboard now.
We have to break orbit.
Take evasive action, Mr. Worf.
We're staying here.
Sir, I must ask you
to reconsider.
I do not know when we will
be able to come back for you.
You have your orders, Commander.
Aye, sir.
Good luck.
What are you looking at?
We have work to do.
Yes, sir.
You heard the Captain.
Sir, what are your orders?
There's only one order,
Lieutenant.
We hold.
We need to find out how many
Jem'Hadar troops landed
and where they are.
Well, you're not going
to learn anything
with a tricorder.
We jam their sensors,
they jam ours.
That's how it works.
Except they have an advantage...
they know where we are.
But that's all they know.
They don't know
our defense position
or how many of us there are.
All things considered
I'd still rather be
in their shoes.
Anything, Ensign?
Plenty. I can hear Vargas'
stomach grumbling
and Ezri tuning
a phase amplifier
with a coil spanner
in the communications bunker.
What about the Jem'Hadar?
Not a sound.
If they're out there,
they're being very quiet.
They're out there.
Keep your ears open, Ensign.
I will, sir.
See anything?
Uh-uh.
That knife you're working on...
it's not Starfleet issue.
Can I see it?
You're supposed to be listening
for the Jem'Hadar.
I know.
Then shut up and listen.
Here they come.
There's something wrong.
They're not firing.
Hold your fire!
Wh-where'd they go?
They weren't here to begin with.
Holograms.
I don't understand.
It was a way for them to see
what they were up against
determine our numbers.
And pinpoint our positions.
Without risking
any casualties... smart.
Oh, yeah.
They're smart, all right
and we're as good as dead!
Not yet we aren't.
Is it over?!
For now.
But the next time
they won't send holograms.
Get that stretcher.
Let's get him to the Infirmary.
Does that mean we stop
working on
the communications array?
They'll have to get along
without you for a while.
We have to find the Houdinis
and disarm them.
I'm all for that.
These mines are a nasty piece
of engineering.
They're also impossible
to detect.
I'm sorry, Captain
but I'm an engineer,
not a magician.
Larkin says
you like a challenge.
I thought I did,
but after banging my head
against that
communications array
for the last few months,
I'm not so sure anymore.
He's just being modest, Captain.
Chief O'Brien would be proud
to have him on his crew.
I can't think of higher praise.
Now what?
Now we get to pull a rabbit
out of our hat.
Here.
You need to keep
your strength up.
Thanks, Uncle, but I
can get my own food.
What's the matter?
Afraid of looking weak
in front of the hu-mans?
I want to earn their respect
if that's what you mean.
At the price of your soul?
Look at you...
you hold that phaser rifle
as if it were made
of pure latinum.
We're in the middle of a war
and this rifle
can keep me alive.
I'm a Starfleet Officer.
You're a Ferengi
and I wish
you'd start acting like one.
You mean, hiding under a rock
every time trouble starts?
I'll tell you one thing,
Nephew...
if the Federation had listened
to the Ferengi Alliance
there never would have been
a war.
Because we would have
surrendered a long time ago.
No. We would have reached
an accommodation.
We would have sat down
across a negotiation table
and hammered out
a peace treaty.
One that both sides
could live with.
You make it sound so simple.
Rule of Acquisition 125:
"You can't make a deal
if you're dead."
Nog.
I'm sending you,
Larkin and Reese
out on a scouting patrol.
Yes, sir.
I need to know
what I'm up against...
how many Jem'Hadar are out there
where they're camped
and what kind of weapons
they have with them.
When do we leave?
Right away.
Hold on a minute!
Why Nog, when you have
all these veterans
to choose from?
No one asked your opinion.
Our tricorders aren't working.
But my hearing is.
Exactly.
You can count on me, sir.
I'll find the Jem'Hadar.
Let's go.
Nog, wait a minute...
He has his orders, Quark.
That is so easy for you to say.
But I bet you wouldn't
send Jake out there.
Jake is not a Starfleet Officer.
You did it.
Actually, I'm not sure
it was me.
It could have been
Tobin or Jadzia.
It doesn't matter.
The point is, you managed
to cut through
the jamming signals.
Unfortunately,
I can't extend its range
past a hundred meters.
That's enough to scan
the entire compound.
Now the question is:
How do we calibrate
the tricorder
to locate the mines in subspace?
Maybe we could try cross-linking
the optronic and isodyne relays.
You're sure
you're not an engineer?
In nine lives, I've been
a little of everything.
Doesn't that...
doesn't that get confusing?
You have no idea.
Really.
I'll give you an example.
This is my first time
on the front lines.
You're talking about Ezri now?
Right.
But Torias, Curzon and Jadzia,
they were in battle many times
and I can remember
what that felt like.
I remember the fear
and the anger
and the adrenaline surge.
Having someone else's memories
of being in combat is one thing.
Living through it yourself...
is another.
I suppose I'm going to find out.
You'll do fine.
This is close enough, Nog.
What is it?
What's going on?
It's time to go.
Right.
Let's go.
Psst!
Someone's coming!
Don't shoot!
It's me... Reese!
Stretcher!
Nog!
What happened?!
Jem'Hadar patrol.
Larkin?
She's dead.
Damn!
The Ferengi found
the encampment.
It's three kilometers
south of here.
- How many troops?
- Two columns.
How we ever going
to hold off two columns?
We'll have to even out the odds.
Any ideas?
I'm working on it.
Captain...
...the kid did all right.
The doctor doesn't want
anybody in there.
Well, how's Nog?
It's a little late for you
to care about that, isn't it?
Quark...
He's going to lose his leg.
Does that answer your question?
Now what happens?
You will be able
to replace the leg, won't you?
As soon as we can get him
to a hospital
he can be fitted
with a biosynthetic limb.
Unfortunately, there,
uh... may be complications.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nog suffered
severe thermal damage
to his femoral motor nerves,
and I'm not sure they'll be able
to stimulate
artificial muscle tissue.
In fact, there's
no way of knowing
until after the operation
has been performed.
I have to get inside.
We've got to get Nog
to a hospital.
We will as soon as we can.
That's not good enough.
I'm sorry.
Sorry?
If you really cared about Nog
you'd never have sent him
out on that patrol.
Now you listen to me, Quark
because I'm only going
to say this one time.
I care about Nog
and every solider
under my command, understood?
Every single one.
Captain...
At ease, Ensign.
I'm sorry, sir.
About what?
About Larkin.
I led her right into a trap.
You found the Jem'Hadar camp.
I... I heard them coming,
but it was too late.
There was all this phaser fire
and I went down...
Nog...
...before I could...
...listen to me.
You followed orders.
You did
what you were trained to do.
I'm proud of you.
Thank you, sir.
It doesn't hurt.
You'd think it would,
but it doesn't.
I'm glad.
I'm going to be fine.
Captain...
the communications array...
it's worth it, right?
I hope to God it is.
Benjamin, sorry to interrupt.
We're ready.
Remember, no one moves
until I say so.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
Now all we have to do
is figure out
how to disarm them.
We're not going to disarm them.
We're going to use them.
This is their camp,
this is ours.
There are mountains
to the east and west
which means they have to come
through this ravine
to get to us.
Then that's where we'll
relocate the mines.
Moving them shouldn't be
too difficult.
Delicate, but not difficult.
I also want you
to reprogram them
so that they're triggered
by movement.
Make sure it's lots of movement.
We want that ravine
full of Jem'Hadar
when those Houdinis
start to go off.
I think we can manage that.
That should take out
a third of their forces.
What's the matter, old man?
Don't you think it'll work?
It's not that.
It's just that a few hours ago,
we thought of these mines
as the kind of ruthless weapon
only the Dominion
would use, but now...
They become
a whole lot friendlier.
Sooner or later, the Jem'Hadar
are going to come
through those barricades
and when they do,
the fewer there are
the better our chances
of survival.
You have your orders.
Power packs.
Did you hear that?
I didn't hear anything.
Relax. When they get here,
you'll know it.
Power packs.
I'm sorry.
My, uh, thumb
got a little nervous.
I know how you feel.
I wonder
if the Jem'Hadar get jittery
before a battle.
I wouldn't count on it.
In that small...
What the hell is that?
Shh, listen.
...park across the way
The children's carousel
The chestnut trees
The wishing well
I'll be seeing you
In every lovely summer's day
In everything
that's bright and gay
I'll always
think of you that way...
Your idea?
Yeah, I thought we could all use
a little Vic Fontaine
right about now.
How's Nog?
There isn't much
I can do for him
until I get him back
to the station.
I take it you were able
to move the mines.
Put it this way, I wouldn't go
for a stroll
through that ravine tonight.
I wasn't planning on it
but then again,
I wasn't planning on being here.
I can see
you've done that before.
Too many times.
Funny... I joined Starfleet
to save lives.
...when the night is new...
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you.
Maybe they're not coming.
Maybe they're turning back.
Maybe we got them all.
Fire!
Kellin?
Kellin?!
You alive?
Captain...
are you with us?
I think so.
We held.
Those were our orders, sir.
Captain.
Yes, Mr. Worf.
The USS Veracruz
has entered orbit.
They're beaming down
troop replacements
and an engineering crew.
What about our people?
Dr. Bashir is aboard
the Veracruz
with Nog and the
rest of the wounded.
They will be taken to a hospital
on Starbase 371.
Good.
I'll return
to the Defiant shortly.
This was a great victory
one worthy of story and song.
It cost enough.
This way.
You two, sector four.
Children.
Not for long.
Ready?
Let's go.
Sisko to Defiant.
Three to beam up.
Sir, the latest casualty reports
have just been posted.
How many this time?
Including the troops lost
at AR-558... 1,730.
Seventeen hundred thirty...
It's a lot of names.
They're not just names.
It's important we remember that.
We have to remember.