What can I get for you?
Uh, Til'amin froth
for me, please.
Romulan ale, Quark.
A glass of spring wine.
Since when do you drink
spring wine?
Or anything else,
for that matter?
It's for Kira.
She should be getting
out of services any minute now.
Well, here she is.
Ah.
How was it?
Ah, beautiful.
Ranjen Telna gave
a very moving sermon.
What was it about?
About how important
it is to forgive
the people who have wronged you.
Hmm. Two hours on forgiveness.
It's a complicated
subject, Odo.
Hmm...
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's just that, uh...
you spend
so much time in services
that sometimes it makes me
wish I were a believer
so that we could go together.
That's so sweet.
I would love
for you to come with me
but I don't think
you'll get much out of it
if you don't believe
in the Prophets.
Ah.
Perhaps if I had
an Orb experience.
It doesn't work like that.
Faith has to come first.
That's too bad.
I have a feeling
it must be very comforting
to believe in something
more powerful than yourself.
If you really feel that way
there are other faiths.
Would it bother you
if Odo believed in...
Klingon religion?
Not if he got
something out of it.
He'd get to eat
the hearts of his enemies.
And go to Sto-Vo-Kor
when he dies.
You could go
on a vision quest.
But...
then I wouldn't get to go to
services with Kira, would I?
That's the whole point.
That really is so sweet.
Yes?
Vedek Fala.
Nerys.
What a surprise.
What are you doing here?
Well, I came to see you.
Oh! Well, come in.
Sit down.
Let me get you some tea.
When I contacted the University
they told me you were
on a spiritual retreat?
Oh, you know me...
always searching for answers.
That's what makes you different
from all
the other vedeks I know.
To you, faith is a journey.
Thank you.
And one that never ends.
Oh, you're a Colonel now.
Seems like only yesterday
you were just a little girl
squirming in your chair
during instruction.
We didn't have any chairs
at the camp.
Uh-uh. We sat on the floor.
Huh. Which was good
for discipline
and made me seem
more imposing.
Oh, as if you needed the help.
"Nerys, what are the three keys
to enlightenment?"
And the answer?
Charity, humility and faith.
You remember.
You were a good teacher.
Without you, I'm not sure
I would have survived that camp.
I brought you something.
What is it?
Welcome to Empok Nor.
Empok Nor?
That's impossible.
I know it's a long way
from Deep Space 9, but...
this transponder allowed
us to beam you here.
Those red armbands...
you're members
of the Pah-wraith cult?
We worship the true Prophets,
yes.
Why did you bring me here?
Well, that is a question
best answered by the Master.
And who exactly is the Master?
I am.
Dukat.
You? You're the leader
of the Pah-wraith cult?
I'm sure you have
many questions, Nerys
and I intend to answer them all.
Leave us, please?
First of all, let me apologize
for bringing you here
without your permission.
Oh, it's all right.
I always wanted
to see Empok Nor.
Is the Dominion aware
that you've, uh,
set up a temple here?
Oh, this station has been
abandoned a long time.
There's no reason
why they'd object
to us putting it to use.
Your hair... you changed it.
Your ear... you've pierced it.
Ah...
A symbol of the covenant
I've made with my new family.
Your new family...
Well, it makes sense,
these people
would chose you as their leader.
They worship evil.
The Pah-wraiths are not
what you think, Nerys
and neither am I.
Let me ask you something.
Have you ever wondered
why the Prophets stood
by and did nothing
when Cardassia took over Bajor?
Have you ever asked yourself
how they could allow your people
to suffer as they did?
The Prophets
have a plan for us.
It's not always easy
to see what it is.
Even as you speak those words
you must know
how hollow they sound.
No. There's a much
better explanation...
one that makes perfect sense.
The Prophets are not
the true Gods of Bajor.
The Pah-wraiths are.
They were cast
from the Celestial Temple
because they wanted
to take an active role
in Bajoran life.
Their only crime is that they
cared about your people...
but they were not
allowed to help them
because they'd lost
the battle for heaven
and were forced to flee.
So I guess the ancient texts
just had it all wrong, then.
Oh, come now, Nerys.
You know as well as I do
that history
is written by the victors
but rest assured...
there will be another chapter.
The Pah-wraiths are determined
to reclaim their place
in heaven.
And how would you know that?
They speak to me in visions.
I am their Emissary.
I don't know whether you
believe what you're saying
or if you're faking it...
or if you're just insane.
I have been touched
by the hand of a God.
I'm a changed man.
Oh, I admit
that when I first allowed myself
to become a vessel
for the Pah-wraith
it was purely out of
self-serving reasons.
All I wanted was to help
it enter the wormhole
so it could force
the Prophets out.
It was nothing more than...
a way to exact
vengeance on Sisko.
But I had no idea the effect
it would have on me.
It was only inside of me
for a very short time...
but it opened my heart.
Would that be before
or after you killed Jadzia?
Oh...
That was most unfortunate...
but it couldn't be helped.
The Celestial Temple
itself was at stake
and she was in the way.
Ah, Nerys.
Nerys, I wish I had the words
to describe to you
what it was like
to have the Pah-wraith
within me.
I could feel its love...
for me and for
the Bajoran people.
It made me realize
I still have a role to play
in Bajor's destiny.
You mean, besides
overseeing an occupation
that killed tens of millions?
You have no idea
how much it pains me
to know that I caused
so much suffering
but I am not responsible
for the occupation.
The Prophets are.
You have no right to say that.
They abandoned Bajor.
I was simply walking the path
they laid out for me.
Now I walk
with the true Prophets.
I'm building
a community here, Nerys.
I brought these people
to Empok Nor
so that we could purify
ourselves in preparation
for the day the Pah-wraiths
reclaim the Celestial Temple.
And what's supposed to happen
when that day comes?
The Pah-wraiths have a plan.
When the time is right,
they will reveal it to me.
Hmm.
Something tells me
that their plan
involves you being
ruler of Bajor again.
You're still so full
of anger toward me.
I can only hope that, one day,
you'll let it go.
I brought you here
because I want you
to be a part of our community.
I want you to share in the love
these people have
for one another
in the love they have for me.
No, they don't love you.
You have some kind
of a hold over them
but they don't love you.
Nerys... open your heart to me.
We're bound together
by destiny.
You belong at my side.
Chief.
When did you realize
she was missing?
This morning...
she usually comes by
my office before going to Ops.
Did you check the entry log?
She had a visitor
sometime after 1900 hours.
Whoever it was only stayed
about ten minutes.
Anything, Mr. Worf?
According to the Ops report
only one ship has left
the station since last night...
the morning transport
to Bajor.
Kira was not aboard.
Sir, I'm picking up traces
of tachyon energy.
A transporter beam?
Yeah, with a Dominion signature.
Any chance of tracing it?
I'm afraid not.
The signal's already dissipated.
Their transporters operate over
longer distances than ours.
What's their maximum range?
If the homing transponder
was in place
up to three light years.
There was
a homing transponder, all right.
It was wrapped in this.
Three light years.
For all we know
she could be deep inside
Dominion space by now.
I had a feeling you'd turn up
sooner or later.
I know you're angry with me.
Angry?
I feel sorry for you.
Letting yourself be duped by
Dukat into joining this cult.
I was a member of this "cult,"
as you call it
long before Dukat.
I came to it
toward the end
of the occupation.
It's helped me make sense of...
the suffering
we all had to endure.
In the camp...
you kept us together.
L-it was your faith
in the Prophets
that got us through.
How could you, of all people,
turn your back on them?
They turned their backs on us...
long ago.
The path the Prophets laid out
for us isn't always easy...
but that's no reason
to turn to hate and fear.
"Hate and fear."
You know how often I've heard
those words used to describe us?
Nothing could be further
from the truth.
The Pah-wraith cult
tried to kill the Emissary.
Dukat had nothing
to do with that.
The boy who attacked
Captain Sisko
was acting out
of his own misguided beliefs.
We're a peaceful people.
Then prove it.
Let me go.
Nerys, the Master
brought you here
because he cares about
your spiritual well-being.
"The Master"!
He's using you.
He's taking your beliefs
and twisting them
to suit his own purpose.
You're so stubborn.
That's always been your problem.
Your problem is
you're too trusting.
When Dukat first came to us
I didn't want to accept him
but I came to realize
the Pah-wraiths
had taken this man of evil
and washed him clean.
What could be
more wondrous than that?
How can you forget
all the friends we lost
during the occupation?
How can you forget
all the millions Dukat murdered?
You disappoint me, Nerys.
Of all the things
I tried to teach you
the most important
is the need to forgive.
Some things can't be forgiven.
Let me show you how we live.
I want you to see the community
we're building here
so you'll know you have
nothing to fear from Dukat.
Or from us.
Only one of the fusion
generators is operational
so we don't have power
for things like replicators.
Where do you get your food?
We've turned several
of the lower levels
into hydroponic bays.
What about things like,
uh, medical supplies?
You bring them in from Bajor?
We have a few cargo shuttles.
We're well aware
that you may try and leave us
so you should know
that the docking bays
are being guarded
as is the transporter
we used to bring you here.
While we're
on the subject, am I, uh...
free to move around,
talk to people?
Of course.
It is the Master's hope
that you will come
to see this as your home.
Mika... this is Nerys.
Welcome.
You're getting close.
Could be any time now.
Mika and her husband
have the honor
of being the first to receive
the Master's blessing
to bear children.
You have to get per...
You have to get
permission from Dukat
to have a baby?
Vows of abstinence are part
of our covenant with him.
Exceptions are granted
only when he sees that
a husband and wife
have demonstrated
a true spiritual bond.
I see.
But you don't approve.
In ancient times,
Bajorans understood
the value of denying
worldly pleasures.
Ironic, isn't it
that a Cardassian
would be the one
to lead us back
to the old ways?
Especially a Cardassian
whose appetite for worldly
pleasures is legendary.
That was a long time ago...
before he felt the kiss
of the Pah-wraith.
That was some kiss.
Striking, isn't it?
Benyan is Mika's husband.
Oh... congratulations.
I understand
it isn't easy to, uh...
get permission to have a baby.
The Master told us
you wouldn't
approve of our ways.
He said we should
be patient with you.
Don't go out of your way.
I don't understand
why he brought you here.
- Benyan...
- That's all right.
We all worked very hard
for what we have.
We don't need you or anyone
else to approve of us.
Fair enough.
Don't misunderstand.
I hope you come to feel
the love of the Pah-wraiths
but if you don't,
that's your loss.
No offense.
None taken.
In fact, I've always
found that, uh...
when people try to convince
others of their beliefs
it's because...
they're really just trying
to convince themselves.
I know what I believe.
And that's what scares me.
No offense.
Ba'ja kor'ek, no'la ba'lani,
pah'nom ko'se plusso ma'kora.
Ba'ja kor'ek, no'la ba'lani
Kosst no'valt Amojan,
my children.
Kosst no'valt Amojan.
Let us open our hearts and pray.
Ba'ja kor'ek, no'la ba'lani,
pah'nom ko'se plusso ma'kora.
Ba'ja kor'ek, no'la ba'lani...
Don't.
Dukat!
... plusso...
Stay where you are.
The rest of you
get down on the floor.
I said down on the floor!
Step aside.
No.
Enough, Nerys
unless you're willing
to kill us all.
Now do you understand
how much they love me?
Careful.
No sudden moves.
I removed it
so I could tend to your bruise.
I had a meal prepared for you.
Oh, come now, Nerys...
you haven't eaten anything
since you arrived.
I know what you're thinking...
but really...
what good would it do
to try to kill me?
Even if you succeeded
it wouldn't get
you off Empok Nor.
You'd only make a martyr of me.
You're right.
I don't want anything
to happen to you...
not until your followers
have a chance to see
what a fraud you are.
I love these people, Nerys
and they love me.
I should think
that after what just happened
in the temple,
you'd realize that.
It always comes back to that,
doesn't it, Dukat?
Your desperate need
to win the love of
the Bajoran people.
You just never understood
why we didn't appreciate you.
If it hadn't been for me
the occupation would
have been much worse.
And you want a "thank you"?
You were working people to death
in the Ore Processing Center
but that didn't stop you
from strutting around Terok Nor
picking out Bajoran women
to take to your bed
and actually believing
that they wanted to be there.
You mother did want to be there.
You took her away
from her children.
She did what she had to do
so that we could survive.
She loved me.
Maybe... she convinced herself
that she did
which is a very different thing.
Perhaps you're right.
And if I did, indeed
cause your mother any pain...
I deeply regret it
just as I regret many things
I did in those years.
That's why I'm so glad
the Pah-wraiths
have given me an opportunity
to redeem myself
in the eyes of your people.
How?
By recreating some kind
of idealized version
of the occupation?
'Cause that's what
you've done here.
You have your station back
Bajorans to serve
your every whim
and the best part is,
this time...
they really do love you.
As misguided as that is...
they love you.
I'm so glad you're here, Nerys.
You embody everything
I most admire
about the Bajoran people.
Your passion...
your spirit...
I can see now
why the Pah-wraiths want you
at my side.
And why is that?
Because if I can open
your heart to them
then surely I can
open the heart of any Bajoran.
Your anger is a challenge.
I welcome it.
Because, in the end, it will
only help me better serve
the Pah-wraiths.
Yes.
It's Mika.
She's gone into labor.
Come, Nerys.
I want you to be a witness
at this blessed event.
Ah...
this is a great day for us,
Benyan.
You should be honored
to have fathered
the first child born
to our community.
I only hope that Mika
and I can live up
to the faith
you've shown in us.
Oh, I have no doubt
that you will.
Your family will be
the first of many.
Think of it.
Someday, Empok Nor will ring
with the laughter of children.
You don't approve, Nerys.
Children being raised
to follow the Pah-wraiths?
You can bet I don't approve.
This is a special moment.
I'm not going to ruin it
by arguing with you.
You believe the Prophets
are the true Gods of Bajor.
I believe the Pah-wraiths are.
Let's just leave it at that.
I'd be happy to.
There's just one thing...
we can't both be right.
The Pah-wraiths...
they've sent us a sign.
My children, good news.
Something wondrous has happened.
This infant...
born of the love
between Benyan and Mika
was transformed in her womb
into a living symbol
of the covenant I made with you.
Oh, what a blessed day this is.
There can no longer be any doubt
that the Pah-wraiths
are smiling upon us.
Let us give thanks and praise.
Kosst Amojan pur-ono.
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma
ten'su, fah-jah nori bentu'sa.
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma ten'su,
fah-jah nori bentu'sa.
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma ten'su
Ka'li bor'ek...
Fala, I don't understand this.
You're an intelligent man.
How can you believe
Dukat's story?
It's obvious he's
the child's father.
What's obvious is
you hate him so much
you can't even entertain
the possibility
that a miracle has occurred.
Are you so blind that
you will just believe
anything he says?
I have faith.
I would think you'd understand
what that means.
Nerys, is it beyond
the realm of possibility
that the Pah-wraiths have
sent us this child as a sign?
They have powers
beyond our understanding.
Your Prophets made
an entire fleet
of Dominion ships
vanish into thin air.
What's one child compared
to a miracle like that?
You want to know
what the real miracle is?
That Mika didn't break into
tears in front of her husband.
She was terrified
he wasn't going to believe
Dukat's little performance.
I could see it in her eyes.
You saw what you wanted to see.
If you believe that
this really is a miracle
then you'll let me talk
to the happy couple.
Oh, what's wrong?
Afraid of finding out the truth?
I know the truth.
I just don't want you
making unfounded accusations.
I'll be discreet.
Oh, it's coming along nicely.
Maybe you should make
one of the children
half Cardassian...
to commemorate what happened.
If I'd known, I would have.
Must be quite an honor
to be part
of such a miraculous event.
It is.
Obviously, Dukat
did the right thing
in giving his permission
for you to have a baby.
We prayed together many times.
He wanted to be sure.
Did you ever pray
with him alone?
Yes.
Did Mika?
Nerys...
let's let Benyan
get back to work.
I want to find Mika.
When we do
I trust you'll be more discreet
than you were with Benyan.
I'm sorry.
Why didn't you tell me
the baby was mine?
I didn't know.
I was hoping it wasn't.
Oh, Mika, I'm so sorry
about what happened
that night.
I was weak...
and you were so beautiful.
I've forgiven you.
You know that.
Have you told anyone?
No.
Not even Benyan?
He wants to believe
it was a miracle
but I know he has doubts.
If he ever asks me...
I don't know
if I can lie to him.
Thank you.
He said Mika went this way.
Don't worry.
Everything is going
to be all right.
Wait here until I'm gone
then go back to your quarters
and pray... for strength.
Mika?
Mika.
Mika...
You got to her just in time.
How is she?
The depressurization
caused swelling
in her meningeal tissues.
I'm going to keep her
sedated until morning.
But she will recover.
She'll be fine.
Brin...
seal the Docking Ring,
check all the airlocks.
Let's make sure we never have
another accident
like this again.
An accident?
What happened, Dukat?
Was Mika going to tell everyone
that you're the father
of her child?
Kira...
Is that why you
tried to kill her?
Enough.
Fala, it's all right.
Nerys is obviously upset.
She doesn't know
what she's saying.
Mika isn't going
to lie for you anymore.
Take her to her quarters.
She needs to rest.
Keep him away from her.
Let us all pray
for Mika's recovery.
Ka'la mo'sek
teru-benso, Kosst Amojan...
I failed you.
Forgive my weakness.
Forgive me
for letting temptation
obscure the path
you laid out for me.
When Mika awakes...
and I pray she does...
your children will learn
the truth.
They will turn away from me.
They will turn away from you.
The covenant will be broken.
Don't let that happen.
Tell me what to do.
Please.
It's not time for services.
I'll stay with her
if you want to go.
No. You go.
Kosst no'valt Amojan,
my children.
Kosst no'valt Amojan.
Tonight, as I prayed
the Pah-wraiths sent me
a vision.
They told me
it would be the last one
I'd ever receive from them.
There's a reason...
a wondrous reason.
My children, the Pah-wraiths
have asked us to join them
in their holy quest
to reclaim the Celestial Temple.
To become warriors
in this great battle
we must transform ourselves.
Our corporeal bodies are
not suitable for the task
so we must leave them behind.
In a few hours
at the beginning of a new day,
we will gather together here
for the last time.
We will shed the flesh
that ties us to this world
and deliver ourselves
into the waiting arms
of the Pah-wraiths.
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma ten'su
fah-jah nori bentu'sa.
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma ten'su,
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma ten'su
fah-jah nori bentu'sa.
Ka'li bor'ek, no'ma ten'su,
I've sent a message
to Deep Space 9.
They should be able
to have someone here for you
within a day or so.
I know you're desperate
to keep your followers
from turning against you.
I'm not surprised
you'd kill them
but I can't believe you'd
be willing to die yourself.
You just don't understand,
Nerys.
The Pah-wraiths
are calling me home.
You should be happy.
Happy?
50 people are going to die.
I assure you our deaths...
will be painless.
Promazine...
developed by the Obsidian Order
for use by their operatives
in case of capture.
Not only is death swift
but it reduces the body to dust
within hours
making it unidentifiable
to the enemy.
Dust...
that's all that will remain
of my passage through this
misbegotten universe, Nerys
but it doesn't bother me
because I know I'm going to be
with the Pah-wraiths.
You really believe that.
Good-bye, Nerys.
My children...
the time has come for us
to leave this world behind us.
As we embark on this journey
our hearts are not heavy,
but joyful
because we know
we'll be together
in the holy light
of the Pah-wraiths.
This is a great day for us.
We have proven ourselves worthy
of the Pah-wraiths
and they are calling us home.
This is the means
of our deliverance.
Kosst no'valt Amojan,
my children.
Kosst no'valt Amojan.
Be not afraid.
I love you all.
Dukat!
Oh, no! Stop her!
Don't you see
why he's doing this?
He doesn't want you
to find out the truth.
Are you all right?
Everyone, please...
let us not allow
anything to disturb
this holy moment.
What's wrong, Dukat?
Take it.
They're all the same,
aren't they?
My children, listen to me.
Tell them, Dukat.
Tell them you never
had any intention
of dying with them.
My time here is not finished.
The Pah-wraiths want me
to continue bringing others
into their light.
This is his child.
That's why you tried
to kill Mika!
The Pah-wraiths
have forgiven my sins.
They've given me
their absolution.
Who are you to presume
they're wrong?
Who are you to judge me?!
You've been making us fools
this whole time!
Liar!
Then it's done.
Our covenant... is broken!
None of you will ever know
the love of the Pah-wraiths...
none of you!
False Gods!
Fala, no!
Why?
Faith... Nerys...
faith.
I'm sorry about Vedek Fala.
I keep going over what he
said when he died, and...
and I don't know if he
was trying to tell me
that he never lost his faith
or he felt betrayed by it.
I suppose you'll never know...
but one thing is certain.
These people have been betrayed
and now they have to find a way
to pick up the pieces
and move on.
I thought Dukat was just
claiming to share their faith
because he wanted
them to love him
but it was more than that.
He's changed.
If you hadn't stopped him,
he would've killed them all
and nobody would've known his
body wasn't among the remains.
That sounds like
the same old Dukat to me.
I know this is going
to sound crazy...
but I think Dukat
convinced himself
that he was doing what
the Pah-wraiths wanted.
Who knows?
Maybe he was.
Either way, he believes
and that makes him more
dangerous than ever.