What if I say something dumb?
Something that makes
him uncomfortable?
Like what?
Like, "How's your new leg?"
I think he's probably
expecting a few questions.
I just don't want
to say the wrong thing.
You'll be fine.
But maybe I shouldn't
be there when he arrives.
Why?
Well, when he was
in the hospital
he didn't answer
any of my letters.
That's okay.
I'm only his stepmother.
But he's going through
something so personal
maybe he only wants
his real family around.
You are real family.
That's right
and you should both just relax.
Yes, Nog has lost a leg
and that's a
traumatic experience
but nothing you do
or say is going
to be worse than what
he's already gone through.
Just be happy to see him
and tell him you love him.
For today, that'll be enough.
They've docked.
- Welcome aboard.
- Thanks.
Aha, there you are.
Hi.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Colonel, are you sure
this is the right transport?
I checked the passenger list
this morning.
He definitely boarded it.
Here he comes.
Welcome back, Nog.
It's good to have you home.
Welcome home, Nog.
Thank you.
It's good to be back.
My orders, Captain.
"Medical leave"?
How could that be?
Sounds like an excuse
to loaf around
while the rest of us work.
Hard work and plenty of it...
that's what I prescribe.
Captain, maybe he
forged those orders.
I'm afraid they're genuine.
"Ensign Nog has no duties
until further notice."
Except... to attend
a "Welcome Home"
party in the Wardroom.
If it's all the same to you, sir
I'm rather tired.
I'd rather just go
to my quarters.
Is that all right?
Absolutely.
We can celebrate
once you've settled in.
Great.
I can carry your bag.
I've got it.
Well, if you'll all excuse me.
...and Julian and Miles
have become even more obsessed
with their Alamo program,
if you can believe it.
I half expect Miles
to start wearing
a coonskin cap to work.
You see, Davy Crockett
wore this cap...
made of raccoon skin and...
I know the program.
Oh.
Well, I think we've covered
just about everything
you missed
while you were away.
Is there anything
you want to talk about?
Not particularly.
Here it comes.
What?
The "cane problem."
You're about to ask me why
I need to walk with a cane
since Dr. Benbasset told you
my biosynthetic leg works
perfectly.
He also told you the problem's
all in my head, that I'm crazy.
He didn't say that.
That's what he thinks.
Forget what he thinks.
What do you think?
Why do you need the cane?
My leg hurts.
And if I put
my full weight on it
it hurts more, so I have to limp
and that means I need
to walk with a cane.
That sounds reasonable to me.
Good.
Look, can I be perfectly honest
with you?
I've spent the last three weeks
talking about my feelings
with the counselors
on Starbase 235
and to tell you the truth,
I'm a little sick of it.
I just want to be left alone
for a while.
I understand.
I think we've
done enough for today.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Computer, what time is it?
The time is 0932 hours.
I'll be seeing you
In all
the old familiar places
That this heart
of mine embraces...
Jake says he's been sleeping
over 18 hours a day
and Julian says he's missed
his last two physical
therapy appointments.
And his counseling sessions
have been going nowhere.
In his words,
he's "sick of talking
about his feelings."
I can't say I blame him.
He's been under constant
psychiatric care
for almost two months now.
What should we do?
I'm not sure.
For now, I think our best bet
is to simply watch and wait.
Not my first choice.
I know
but sometimes a patient
can help guide
his own treatment.
Let's see what Nog does next.
...but I'll be seeing you.
I'll be seeing you
In all the old
Familiar places...
Nog, I am trying
to be understanding
and I want to be your friend
but enough is enough!
You've been playing that same
stupid song for three days.
I-I can't take it anymore.
Aren't you going
to say anything?
You've barely said three words
to me since you came home.
Maybe I don't have
anything to say.
I'm trying to help you here, Nog
but you're not making it easy.
You want to help me? Fine.
Leave me alone.
All right. Okay.
But if you want to hear
that song again
go rent a holosuite!
Program is running.
You may enter when ready.
Hi, there, pally.
Gee, it's good to see you.
Vic Fontaine.
I know. I'm Nog.
You're Rom's kid, right?
Right.
He's really proud of you.
He's always in here bragging
about his son,
the soldier boy.
Yeah.
What can I do for you?
I want to hear
"I'll Be Seeing You."
Sure thing, kiddo.
Any other requests?
No. Just...
"I'll Be Seeing You."
Sounds like a special tune.
It is.
It helped me once
when I was... unhappy.
What more can you ask
from a song?
"I'll Be Seeing You."
From the top.
I'll be seeing you
In all the old,
familiar places...
Doctor...
That this heart
of mine embraces...
Yes?
What is that?
It's a song that I had
Vic Fontaine record for me.
Vic...
Yes. He's a character
in a holosuite program of mine.
I thought it might take
our minds off our troubles.
Is it bothering you?
No. It's kind of nice.
...the chestnut tree
The wishing well
I'll be seeing you
In every lovely summer's day
In everything
That's bright and gay
I'll always think of you...
...l'll find you
in the morning sun
And when the night is new
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you
I'll find you
in the morning sun
And when the night is new
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you.
Thank you.
Take five, fellas.
Okay, kid, I know
15 different arrangements
of that song.
You've heard them all.
Now which one's your favorite?
The first.
Somehow, I knew you
were going to say that.
So let me guess... Julian
played it for you, right?
Right.
If I had him as a publicist
I'd be bigger than Elvis.
Who?
Never mind.
So... how's the new leg?
You know about that?
People talk.
If you really want to know...
it hurts.
Can they give you something
for that?
No. They say
it's all in my head.
"According to my tricorder
"the pain receptors in your leg
aren't being stimulated, Nog.
You must be imagining it."
But I don't care what they say.
It hurts all the time.
I believe you.
You're the only one.
So what else can I do for you?
Sing it again?
No.
Good.
To tell you the truth
I was starting to get
a little sick of it myself.
How about something else?
No.
I just want to go to bed.
Okay, kid.
Catch you later, huh?
Yeah.
Something wrong?
I don't want to go
back to my quarters.
Actually, I don't want
to go back to my life.
Vic...
where do you live?
In the program, I mean.
Do you have a house or...
I have a suite
here in the hotel.
Do you have an extra room?
Sure. You want to stay
with me tonight?
Maybe more than just tonight.
Officially, I'm on medical leave
and according to regulations
I can choose
my rehabilitation facility.
You want to choose a holosuite
program for your rehab?
Why not?
Okay, kid...
if that's the way you want it
from now on,
you're staying with me.
Great.
Crazy.
My son is insane.
Rom...
He's a one-legged crazy man!
He is not crazy.
But he is living in a holosuite.
At first, it struck me
as a little... peculiar
but after I thought it over,
I began to think
that this might be
a good sign after all.
How can hiding
in one of Julian's
adolescent programs
be a good sign?
Hey...
It could be worse.
He could be hiding
in the Alamo program.
Or that ridiculous
secret agent program.
Hey...
Or that stupid Viking program.
Hey!
All right.
Are you sure
this is in Nog's best interest?
No, I'm not sure
but I think Nog might be
subconsciously trying
to seek out his own
form of therapy.
I'm sorry, but moving
into a holosuite isn't my idea
of therapy.
Okay.
It sounds a little odd.
It sounds
- ridiculous.
- Not really.
I'm inclined to agree
with Ezri on this one.
The mind has a strong natural
instinct for survival.
Now, for whatever reason,
Nog's mind has chosen
to take shelter in the
world of Vic Fontaine.
I think we should wait
and see how this plays out.
Then someone should talk
to Vic, make him aware
of Nog's emotional
and physical condition.
I'll do it.
And who's going to be paying
for all this holosuite time?
I guess I am.
And it's very generous of you.
Keep me informed.
I get it.
He's got some healing to do.
I could spot that
the moment he walked in here.
Great.
Do you have any questions?
You sure he doesn't
need the cane?
Because he's
pretty sure he does.
I'm positive.
It's a psychological need,
not a physical one.
Well, then I have some ideas
on how to wean him
off the stick.
Okay, but don't push it.
Do I seem pushy to you?
No. Well, you know
how to reach me
if you have any problems.
I got your number.
So you're Jack Wilson.
What's that mean
to you, Shane?
Hey, kid.
Hey, Vic.
Have you seen this movie?
Oh, yeah.
What have you heard, Shane?
I've heard that you're
a lowdown Yankee liar.
Shane, look out!
From these books, I can't tell
if I'm as rich as Rockefeller
or poor as a church mouse.
It's not real money, Vic.
Don't worry about it.
Hey, it's real to me, kid.
Well, I can have the computer
put some money in your account.
No, thanks.
I'll figure it out.
I got to be going on.
Why, Shane?
Didn't he just get shot
a minute ago?
Yeah.
He took one in the arm.
He's not bleeding.
He's not even in pain.
Noggles, take it easy.
It's only a movie.
Shane!
Come back!
I like The Searchers better.
Yeah. Who doesn't?
Son of a gun.
I got to get ready for the show.
Show? I thought
we were hanging in.
No, "hanging out."
And we are, except
I have a gig to do.
Cancel it.
I can't do that.
Why not?
It would be unprofessional.
Besides, performing is my life.
It's what I do.
I got to get out there
and swing.
Otherwise, I'm just
another Clyde in a tux.
You coming to the show?
Sure.
Good.
Then, may I suggest you, uh...
carry something
with a little more...
style?
Now, this is a cane.
It's a replica
of the one Errol Flynn
used to have...
only his was a little taller.
It's beautiful.
It reminds me
of the Grand Nagus' staff.
It has a little secret.
Push that button at the back
of the head.
Great! But what's it for?
You never know when a lady's
going to need a light.
Now, be careful with that stick.
It's fragile.
It might not hold
your whole weight.
Actually, I don't need
to put my whole weight on it.
Good.
Now, let's get dressed.
Tuxedos?
You're catching on.
I've got a song that I sing
I can make the rain go
Any time I move my finger
Lucky me
Can't you see I'm in love?
Life is a beautiful thing
As long as
I hold that string
I'd be a silly so-and-so
If I should ever let it go
I've got the world
on a string
Sittin' on a rainbow
Got the string around my finger
What a world...
Hey, have you seen Nog?
I think I see him sitting
right over there.
All right, thanks.
Life is a beautiful thing
As long
as I hold that string...
Hi, there.
Nog, let me introduce you to...
Down in front.
Sorry.
Nog, this is Kesha.
Kesha, Nog.
Nice to meet you.
Welcome to Las Vegas.
Thanks.
...around my finger
What a world, what a life
I'm in love.
Thank you, thank you.
You're too kind.
I guess that's
the response you get
when you pack the house
with relatives.
So, uh, what
have you been doing?
Hanging out.
Out of what?
It's an expression.
There's a lot of
old Earth slang in this program.
Right, daddy-o?
Right.
Why don't I get us
some drinks, huh?
Kesha, what'll you have?
A Makara fizz.
They don't serve that here.
Oh. Well, what are you having?
A martini. Two olives.
I'll have the same.
Okay. I'll be right back.
...Now you're here
And now I know
just where I'm going...
Jake says you're going to be
the first Ferengi Captain
in Starfleet.
We'll see.
He also says
you're quite a hero.
I'm not a hero.
Don't be so modest.
Jake's not the only one.
Everyone on the station...
I said
I'm not a hero.
Okay.
...Now you're here
And now I know
just where I'm going
No more doubts...
Which one?
What?
That's what you're wondering,
right?
Which leg is it?
Uh, no, I wasn't wondering
about that.
About what?
About your... you know...
My new leg?
Can't you say it?
No. Yes.
I mean, I'm not trying
to say anything.
Then maybe
you should just keep quiet.
Okay. Here we go.
Three martinis.
I think
we should leave, Jake.
Sounds like a good idea.
What's going on?
It's all my fault.
I didn't mean to stare.
At what?
What do you think?
Oh.
I'm really sorry
if I made you uncomfortable,
Nog.
Wonderful.
Good-bye.
Hold on.
She said she was sorry.
I heard her.
Now you can go.
Nog, what's wrong with you?
I said get out!
Nog...
Let me put it another way.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Break it up.
You all right?
Yeah. I'm fine.
And you, take a hike.
What?
You heard me.
You don't come into my club
and start hitting customers.
Now, get out
before I throw you out.
You're still up?
I couldn't sleep.
Do you mind?
What a night.
I'm sorry about what happened.
Don't apologize to me.
I'm not the one you belted.
I'll settle things with Jake.
And his girl.
Absolutely.
Can I go back
to the club tomorrow night?
I can't have you
hitting the customers.
It's not good for business.
I promise it'll
never happen again.
What got into you, anyway?
I don't know.
She started calling me
a hero, and...
things just went
downhill from there.
She called you a hero
and for that you slugged
your best friend?
Remind me never to give
you a compliment.
You know, I'm beat.
That's never happened to me.
What?
Being tired.
My program's never run
this long.
Usually people come in,
ask for a song or two...
sometimes a night on the town...
but I never have to put in
a full day.
Maybe you should go to bed.
I got work to do.
If I don't get
these books in order
Uncle Sam's going
to come down on me
like a ton of bricks.
Sounds like my uncle.
Is there anything I can do?
You know anything
about bookkeeping?
I'm a Ferengi.
It's in our blood.
Be my guest.
Where's your computer?
Right here.
It's 1962.
What do you want from me?
It's all right.
I can do it this way.
I'm going to hit the sack.
Can I ask you a question, Vic?
Sure.
When you sleep...
do you dream?
Good night, kid.
Good night, Vic.
So, when Dino goes in
to pick up his robe
he doesn't realize
that across the back
Frank has printed in
big bold letters...
I'll finish the story later.
Hi, dollface.
Hi.
Where's Nog?
Up in the room...
still working on
the receipts from '61.
That kid's a hell
of an accountant.
He said the government
owes me money.
Can you believe that?
I need to talk to him.
Can it wait?
I'm afraid not.
It's about that thing
with Jake, right?
Is he pressing charges?
No. But I do think
that it's time for Nog
to leave the holosuite.
Wait-wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
He likes it here.
He's making progress.
Okay, he lost his cool.
But I don't think
that'll happen again.
Vic, he can't hide
in here forever.
He has to face reality sometime.
The kid's had too much
reality lately
if you ask me.
He's lost a leg.
He's watched good friends die.
Like you said,
we shouldn't push him.
He needs time to heal.
No offense, but you're
just a hologram
and I am his counselor.
I outrank you
and I feel that it's
time for him to go.
He's on medical leave
and according
to Starfleet Regulations
he can spend it
wherever he chooses.
How do you know that?
I told him.
And if you try
to force me to leave
I'll resign my commission.
Wait a minute.
Let's slow down here.
No one's talking about
forcing anyone to do anything.
Good.
Because Vic and I
have big plans.
We do?
I've been going
over your books,
and this place
is a latinum mine
and you don't even know it.
In my opinion
it's time to expand
the business.
Nog, this is a holosuite.
Of course it's a holosuite.
But that doesn't mean
we can't build a new casino.
A new casino?
How much money do I have?
If you'll excuse us,
Counselor.
We have business to conduct.
Say, it's only a paper moon
Sailing over a cardboard sea
But it wouldn't be
make-believe
If you believed in me
Now it's only a canvas sky
Hanging over a muslin tree
But it wouldn't be
make-believe
If you believed in me
Without your love
It's a honky-tonk parade
It's a melody played
in a penny arcade
It's a Barnum & Bailey
world
Just as phony as it can be
But it wouldn't be
make-believe
If you believed in me
Without your love
It's a honky-tonk parade
It's a melody played
in a penny arcade
It's a Barnum & Bailey
world
Just as phony as it can be
But it wouldn't be
make-believe
If you believed in me
No, it wouldn't be
make-believe
If you believed in me.
Go easy on the garnishes.
People order a drink
they don't want
a fruit bowl in the glass.
We'll talk about this later.
Okay.
Good evening.
I'll take care of them.
Hey, long time no see.
Oh, Nog.
Right this way.
So... how are you?
Couldn't be better.
Business is booming.
We're making money
hand over fist.
I can hardly keep up with
all the profits.
Those are holographic
profits, right?
Yeah.
So, what's new with you?
Well...
Rom got a promotion.
Maintenance Engineer
First Class.
That's great!
Congratulations, Dad.
Thanks.
We should celebrate.
We'll close the lounge.
Have a private party...
Actually, Chief O'Brien
threw him a party last night.
Oh.
It was a spur-of-the-moment
thing.
No invitations or anything.
Don't worry about it.
I probably couldn't
have gotten away.
Last night was really busy.
Uh-oh. Big player
just walked in.
Excuse me a minute.
I need to go schmooze.
Okay.
See you later.
Bye.
Hey, I hope you're
still talking to me.
Of course I am.
I got to hand it to you, Vic.
You've done a great
job with him.
He seems like a new man.
He just needed
a little time, that's all.
Heals all wounds, right?
Giving him that cane
was a great idea.
I haven't seen him
limp in days.
It gets better.
Yesterday, we drove out
to see the architect
who's designing
the new casino.
I saw him actually
run up a flight of stairs.
No kidding?
Would I kid a kidder?
So what's next for you two?
Ah... we don't break ground
on the casino for about a week
so I thought we'd fly up
to Tahoe for a couple of days.
Sammy's going to be performing
at the Cal-Neva
and I thought I'd introduce
the kid to him.
Sammy's a friend of yours?
Yeah. We're tight.
I see.
You're going to get
Sammy to convince him
that it's time to
leave the holosuite.
Well... no...
Forget it.
I should know better by now
than to ask you to give
away your secrets.
You probably have the
whole thing mapped out.
I mean, what am I thinking?
That this new casino
is anything more than a ploy?
That you'd actually let him
live out the rest of
his life in a holosuite?
No.
Of course not.
I mean...
the casino's just a...
just a ploy
like you said, you know.
They'll be so glad
to have him back.
Yeah.
He is better, isn't he?
It's like you said...
he just needed a
break from reality.
Now all that's left
is to decide
when he's ready to go back.
But I'll leave that up to you.
See you around.
See ya.
Great set tonight, Vic.
Thanks.
Lots of familiar
faces in the crowd.
Did I see Rom
and Leeta out there?
They came for a while.
What do you think about
moving the crap tables
over to the south wing
and expanding the slot
machines out into here?
Good idea.
I'll think it over.
But we're supposed
to meet with the architect
tomorrow morning.
Not anymore.
It's time for you to go, kid.
Go where?
You know where.
It's time to end the program.
But we've got work to do.
We have a casino to build.
No, we don't.
This is just a fantasy.
It's not real.
It's real to me
and it's real to you
and don't say it isn't.
I know better.
You're right.
It's very real to me.
But I'm a hologram, Nog.
I'm not a person.
Until you came along,
I'd never been on
for more than six or
seven hours straight.
I know.
And now you're
running all the time.
Isn't it great?
It's incredible.
Since you've been here
I've slept in a bed every night,
gone to work every day...
had time to read the paper,
play cards with the boys.
I've had a life
and I have to tell you
it's a precious thing.
I had no idea how much
it means to just... live.
And now I'm going
to return the favor
and give you your life back.
But I don't want that life
anymore, Vic.
I'm perfectly happy here.
What "here"?
There is no "here."
Don't you get it?
This is nowhere.
It's an illusion and so am I.
In fact, the only thing
in this entire program
that is not an illusion
is you.
Okay. You're right...
but I'm not ready
to go back yet.
I need more time.
So let's just sleep on this
and talk about it tomorrow.
Kid...
I hate to do this to you
but you're not giving
me any choice.
Computer...
No! Don't!
End program.
Oh, hi, Nog.
Chief.
Something wrong?
No, no. I, uh...
I was running
a diagnostic in Ops
and I noticed
a magnetic flux anomaly
in the holosuite
transilluminator circuits.
I didn't realize it was you.
Sorry.
I'm just having trouble
getting the Las Vegas
program to run.
You know...
Vic's matrix is
a little different
than your standard
photokinetic hologram.
He can turn himself off.
And if he doesn't
want to appear
he doesn't appear.
You mean, he has free will?
Hey, I'm an engineer,
not a philosopher.
All I know is, that when Vic
turns himself off, he's off
and ripping out the
guts of the holosuite
isn't going to change that.
Anything else I can do for you?
No.
Oh, we, uh... we all
miss you in Ops.
Yeah.
So...
now that the Chief's told you
I'm smarter
than the average bear
will you stop messing around
with my holosuite?
If you turn the program back on.
What is it I'm not making
clear to you, Charlie?
You got to go.
Don't you get it?
I can't go out there.
Why not?
I'm scared... okay?
I'm scared.
When the war began...
I wasn't happy or anything
but I was eager.
I wanted to test myself.
I wanted to prove I had
what it took to be a soldier
and I saw a lot of combat.
I saw a lot of people get hurt.
I saw a lot of people die
but I didn't think
anything was going
to happen to me
and then, suddenly
Dr. Bashir is telling me
he has to cut my leg off.
I couldn't believe it.
I still can't believe it.
If I can get shot,
if I can lose my leg
anything can happen to me, Vic.
I could die tomorrow.
I don't know
if I'm ready to face that.
If I stay here, at least I know
what the future
is going to be like.
You stay here,
you're going to die
not all at once,
but little by little.
Eventually, you'll become
as hollow as I am.
You don't seem hollow to me.
Compared to you,
I'm hollow as a snare drum.
Look, kid, I don't
know what's going
to happen to you out there.
All I can tell you is that...
you've got to play
the cards life deals you.
Sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose.
But at least you're in the game.
Crazy.
He seemed happy.
And he's stopped limping.
You're joking.
No. He's a new man.
You should go see him.
I don't think I'll need to.
- Hi.
Are you okay?
No...
but I will be.
Computer, run program Bashir 62.
Hi, kid.
Hey, nice threads.
Thanks.
You back at work?
Limited duty.
Just a couple hours a day.
How's it feel?
Different.
I feel older.
Happens to the best of us.
I want to thank you
for all that you did for me.
That's not necessary.
You did something for me, too.
You gave me a chance
to see what it's like
to have a life.
Well, you're going to
have that chance again.
I've made arrangements
with my Uncle Quark
to keep your program running
26 hours a day from now on.
What?
It's my gift to you.
Kid... I don't know
what to say.
Just put it there, pally
and tell me you'll always
save a seat for me up front.
It's a deal, and you
can take that to the bank.
Got to go.
I'm buying Jake and
Kesha dinner tonight.
Hey.
Try not to overturn
the furniture.
I'll try.
26 hours a day?
I've got the world on string
Sittin' on a rainbow
Got the string
around my finger
What a world
What a life
I'm in love
I've got a song
that I sing
I can make the rain go
Anytime I move my finger
Lucky me
Can't you see
I'm in love?
Life is a beautiful thing
As long as I hold
that string
I'd be a silly so-and-so
If I should ever let it go
I've got
the world on a string
Sittin' on a rainbow
Got the string
around my finger
What a world
What a life
I'm in love
Life is a beautiful thing...