By the way,
your gagh has arrived.
My what?
Oh, no.
Oh, yes,
and it's waiting for you
in Cargo Bay 2.
Your gagh?
Jadzia ordered it.
She was planning a party
for Martok's birthday
next week.
How much gagh did she order?
51 cases.
Each containing
a different variety.
There are varieties of gagh?
Oh, yes. I can remember
what each one tastes like
and the way they feel
when you swallow them.
Torgud gagh wiggles.
Filden gagh squirms.
Meshta gagh jumps.
Are you all right?
Me?
Well, you've barely
said three words.
Something on your mind?
Oh, no. I just, uh...
can't wait to see Miles,
that's all.
Oh, let me guess.
You have
a holosuite appointment...
defending the Alamo again?
You know me too well.
When does his transport arrive?
Half an hour.
Bithool gagh has feet.
Flush it out the airlock,
all of it.
Environmental regulations.
Well, why don't you just
give it to Martok?
He'd insist on sharing it
with me as a point of honor.
Wistan gagh is packed
in targ blood.
I have to go now.
See you later.
I think I'd better go, too.
Give my regards to Santa Anna.
What?
Miles asked me
not to say anything
but, uh, I haven't heard
from him in three days
and since he wasn't on
this morning's transport
I think something might
have happened to him.
He told me he was going home
to visit his father.
He may have implied that he
was going to visit his father
but he didn't actually say it.
Doctor, please.
Yes, sir.
So where is he?
The last message
I received from him
said that he was
still in New Sydney
and that he was following up
on some promising leads.
He's not a detective.
He's an engineer.
He is my Chief Engineer
and now he's missing.
So who is this woman he's
supposed to be looking for?
She's the widow of Liam Bilby.
Bilby? Bilby?
The man he befriended in that
undercover operation last year?
Yes, sir. Miles still feels
responsible for his death
and has been in touch
with his widow ever since
and when she dropped
out of sight three weeks ago
he got worried
and decided to find her.
And now they're both missing.
Perfect.
In his defense, sir
he did try and go through
the official channels
but the authorities
on New Sydney
weren't very cooperative,
to say the least
and since it isn't
a Federation world
Starfleet doesn't have
any jurisdiction.
So he decided to turn
into a one-man police force.
Yes, sir.
New Sydney... it's in
the Sappora system, right?
Right.
I want a written report
detailing everything
you know about this woman
O'Brien's plan to find her
and everything else you
neglected to mention to me.
Aye, sir. May I ask
what you're going to do?
No, you may not
and I want that report
on my desk within the hour.
And since your family
still lives
in the Sappora system,
I thought they might have
a few contacts on New Sydney.
I'm sure they do.
My mother's one of
the more important
business leaders in the system.
Your personnel file
says she owns
the fifth largest
pergium mining facility
in the entire sector.
Actually, it's the sixth now.
The Ferengi found
a large deposit
on Timor II a few years ago.
My mother nearly
had a heart attack
when she found out we'd been
knocked out of the top five.
Please.
Do you think she'd be willing
to intervene
with the local authorities?
To look into what happened
to the Chief?
Oh, I'm sure she would.
That's the first good news
I've heard all day.
Something wrong?
No.
Yes.
I don't know.
I haven't talked to my mother
in almost six months.
Oh.
The last time I saw her
was just after I was joined.
She came to visit me on Trill
and I was still
a little confused.
When she walked into my room
I put on a big smile,
looked her right in the eye
and said, "Hi, Mom.
It's me... Curzon."
Things kind of went
downhill from there.
I'm sure she understood
what you were going through.
You weren't prepared
to be joined.
She couldn't blame you
for being confused.
She didn't, not really
but she did want me
to come home to recuperate
and we had a... disagreement.
Not for the first time?
No, not for the first time.
If there was any other way,
I wouldn't ask you to do this.
No. That's all right.
I mean, my family problems
aren't as important
as finding the Chief.
I'll call my mother right away.
Thanks, old man.
Any time.
We've been worried about you.
I'm all right.
Really.
And I'm a lot more sure
of who I am
than the last time you saw me.
Well, that's a relief.
I'd hate to have to start
calling you Curzon.
I, uh... I've been promoted.
Oh?
Lieutenant Junior Grade
Ezri Dax, at your service.
Ezri Dax?
The symbiont name
always replaces
the family name
of the new host.
It's traditional.
Of course it is.
I haven't been away
from Trill that long.
The important thing
is you're doing well.
Mother, I'm calling
because I need your help.
One of our officers,
Miles O'Brien
went to New Sydney
three weeks ago,
and now he's missing.
Captain Sisko was wondering
if maybe you could...
I'll do everything I can.
Thank you.
Now... when are you coming home?
I'm not sure
when I can get away.
Ezri, you haven't been home
in three years.
I know
but with the war on
and everything...
Ezri Tigan... Dax...
you tell your Commanding Officer
that your mother
is a very difficult woman
and that she refuses
to help look for Mr. O'Brien
unless you're allowed
to return home right away.
Mother, no.
Please don't put me in...
Ezri, good-bye.
I'll see you when you get here.
Here. Take 20 milligrams
at the first sign
of spacesickness.
If you don't,
you'll regret it.
So will the other passengers.
Everything Starfleet knows
on Bilby and his widow.
Where's your report?
Oh, it's in there.
It's the one
with Captain Sisko's
boot-prints all over it.
Don't worry.
I'm sure you'll be
out of the doghouse
by the time I get back.
I hope so.
Would it help if I
said, that, as someone
who isn't especially
close to his parents
I sympathize?
I'm about to present my family
with a whole new Ezri
and to tell you the truth
they didn't really know
what to make of the old one.
But thanks for trying, Julian.
I'll let you know
as soon as I find out
anything about Miles.
Well, have a safe trip.
Zee.
Norvo.
I cannot believe
you're really here.
Neither can I.
You cut your hair.
Oh... yeah,
it kept getting in my eyes.
Do you like it?
Takes some getting used to.
I think you've just summed up
my entire visit.
Is this yours?
Mom insisted
on hanging it in here.
I hate it.
Why?
Well, the composition
is puerile and obvious
the colors belong
on a child's toy
and the technique is laughable.
But other than that?
It's perfect.
Welcome home, little girl.
Hi, Janel.
Do I have to take
a sonic shower
before I get a hug?
It's good to see you.
You, too.
What happened here?
She cut it.
I think it brings
out her eyes
gives her more
of a classic look.
It's cute.
Um, Mom's on her way.
She said to give you
the preliminary police report
on your friend.
Have they found out anything?
Not yet.
But they have a few leads.
I hope you appreciate
all the trouble
she's going to.
She called in a lot of favors
from the New Sydney police.
Of course I appreciate it.
So how long are you staying?
I'm not sure yet.
She's not going
to be here
a minute longer than she has to.
You know that.
We're in the middle
of a war, Janel.
I have responsibilities
back on DS9.
There's always something.
Hello, Mother.
I hate your hair.
Oh...
Have you eaten?
No, not yet.
Good, because I've
got Korella working
on a very special dinner.
Have you taken care
of Lorkin?
I was just going to contact him.
I want him paid and gone
before dinner's ready.
Yes, ma'am.
And what about that
third quarter review
I asked you for?
I'm still working on it.
You've been working on it
for a week now.
I miscalculated
some of the revenues.
I have to redo them.
I know you don't like
doing the bookkeeping
but I really need that review
as soon as possible, all right?
Good.
I want to show you
the new solarium.
I had these tiles all
brought in from Andoria
and then hand-painted
by this very charming old man...
Have Mr. Lorkin report
to the main house.
Yes, sir.
Why are you getting
rid of Lorkin?
That broken waveguide
in 14-3-A is going to cost us
a thousand bars
of latinum a day.
Mother thinks it's the result
of sloppy maintenance.
What do you think?
I think a brand-new waveguide
doesn't just break.
You mean... Bokar was behind it?
He's trying
to send us a message.
The Orion Syndicate
doesn't take no for an answer.
Maybe we should tell Mother.
No.
I can deal with Bokar.
I don't know...
Relax.
Everything's going
to be all right.
Jadzia considered Kira
to be one of her best friends
and I'm starting to think
of her the same way.
We spend a lot of time together.
She didn't have any trouble
adjusting to having a...
new Dax in her life?
Well, no more than anyone else.
I don't really think any of them
were expecting another Dax
to walk into their lives.
Hmm. Did any of them wonder...
Whatever happened
to that young man
you were interested in
on the Destiny?
It was, uh, Lieutenant,
uh, uh... something.
Brinner Finok.
Yes.
He was an Ensign.
I did talk to him
after I was joined... once
but... I don't think
we're really right
for each other anymore.
He reminds me too much
of my son, Gran.
It makes me uncomfortable
being around him now.
Sorry. Audrid's son Gran.
I'm still
sorting out my pronouns.
I'm sure all joined Trills
go through this.
No, just me.
Nothing simple for Ezri.
There's times when the computer
asks me to identify myself
and I have to think
about what to say.
Or worse yet,
there's days when I wake up
and I don't even know
if I'm a man or a woman
until I pull back the covers.
I also have an unfortunate
tendency to ramble.
Don't be embarrassed, dear.
It's not your fault.
You should have gone
through years of training
to receive a symbiont.
It wasn't fair of them
to join you to Dax
just because you happened to be
the only Trill on board.
I mean, it's no surprise to me
you're having trouble
sorting out eight lifetimes
of memories and experiences.
Well, it can be
a little overwhelming at times.
Sure.
But don't you worry.
We'll take care of you,
won't we?
Absolutely.
Of course.
That's nice to know
but I think I've got things
under control now.
Ezri...
you always were too
proud for your own good.
Come in, Zee.
How did you know it was me?
No one else would bother
with the chime.
Hmm, I see some things
never change.
Here...
have a seat.
How many of these are yours?
All of the bad ones.
When did you become
such a harsh critic
of your work?
Just being realistic.
It's amateurish, I know that.
It says so right there.
Saurian brandy?
Sure.
I should probably
get a clean one.
I don't care.
Norvo, this doesn't mean...
To my sister...
a shining angel in a dark sky.
All right.
The Andorian Academy
rejected your application.
That doesn't mean
your work is amateurish.
There are other art schools.
It's the best.
So? You shouldn't just quit.
I'm not very good, Zee.
I never was.
All of this...
it's an indulgence.
Just like my other hobbies...
poetry, music...
I can't... concentrate.
My mind wanders.
I don't have the discipline
it takes to succeed.
Those are Mother's words.
I know,
because I've heard them, too.
She wasn't right about me
and she's not right
about you, either.
I'm fine with the way
things turned out. Really.
Besides, they need me here.
To do what,
the family bookkeeping?
Norvo, you could do
so much more.
I'm not trying
to make you feel bad.
I just want you to know
that I still believe in you.
Thanks. Thank you.
Good night.
Night.
I hope you're satisfied.
Have you seen Norvo today?
No.
Well, maybe you should.
He's lying in bed
with a hangover.
When I woke up this morning
I found him passed out
in the entry room.
Evidently, he spent
most of the night doing this.
You think it's funny?
I think it's funny you think
he did this because of me.
He's not happy here, Mother.
Can't you see that?
That's nonsense.
Mother, he's defacing
his own artwork...
work you insisted on displaying
even after he objected.
I'm proud of him.
I'm trying to encourage him.
But what you've done
is made him feel
trapped and powerless.
You've barely spent
one night in this house
and you think you can
analyze our entire family?
You don't know
your brother anymore, Ezri.
He's a fragile young man
who needs to be cared for.
He is a grown man
who needs his freedom.
You're smothering him.
How dare you come in here
and tell me how to be a mother?
What do you know
about raising children?
Actually, I have three...
no, four lifetimes' worth
of memories
about raising children.
I have worked and sacrificed
for each one of you
for over 30 years.
Not now!
Sorry to interrupt, but...
Miles!
Ezri...
what are you doing here?
This is... my home.
This is where I live.
Uh... my mother.
I'm pleased to meet you,
Mr. O'Brien.
Can you?
He wasn't very friendly
when we located him.
Neither were you.
If you'll excuse me,
we're having a problem
with a drill down in 24-B.
Did you do this to him?
Just the one on the jaw.
The rest he got thanks
to the Orion Syndicate.
Did you find out anything
on Bilby's wife?
I found her.
She's dead.
Thanks.
The DNA scan confirmed
that the body was Morica's.
She'd been dead
at least six weeks.
Do you have any idea
of the cause of death?
No.
The cause of death
was the Orion Syndicate.
There's no evidence of that.
L-it could have been
an accident.
Oh, yeah.
She accidentally
hit herself in the head
and accidentally threw herself
in the river, huh?
We pull a dozen bodies a month
out of that river.
You think
they're all Syndicate murders?
If it was anything like this,
yes.
And if you hadn't interfered
I might have proved
she was murdered.
If we hadn't interfered,
you'd be dead.
When your mother called us,
we already had word
that a Starfleet Intelligence
Operative was trying
to infiltrate the Syndicate.
It didn't take long
to realize
that it was your friend.
We found him being beaten up
by a pair of Nausicaans.
They were just trying
to scare me.
Why?
Exactly.
Why were they trying
to scare me?
Because I had found the body
of Morica Bilby
and they didn't want me to trace
the murder back to them.
The Syndicate would never kill
the widow of an operative.
The only thing holding
them together is
this loyalty they show
to operatives
and their families.
They may not be
as loyal as you think.
Mrs. Tigan, please contact
us if there's anything else
we can do for you.
Thank you.
I will.
Ezri, why don't you show
Mr. O'Brien
to one of our guest rooms.
Let him clean up
and have something to eat.
Thanks.
...so that tip led me
to the river.
I searched the south bank
for about three hours
before I found her.
The organic solvents
in the water
had partially
decomposed her body...
but it was her.
I'm sorry, Chief.
I wish there was
something more I could do.
Maybe you could put in
a good word for me
with Captain Sisko.
It may take a lot of good words,
but I'll talk to him.
Mr. O'Brien,
how are you feeling?
Fine, thank you.
I've eaten enough for a week.
Glad to hear it.
I understand
that you're an engineer.
That's right.
He's not a mining engineer.
We have a problem
with a transsonic drill
that no one on my staff
seems capable of fixing
and I would appreciate
it very much
if you would be kind
enough to take a look at it.
Now?
Mother, he needs some rest.
How much rest do you require,
Mr. O'Brien?
Actually, I feel fine.
Thank you.
I'll see you at dinner.
I'm sorry about this.
Our mother is a force of nature.
It's all right.
It'll be good to get my hands
on a problem I can solve
for a change.
Lead on.
Good morning.
Good afternoon.
Oh.
Mother is not going
to be happy about this.
Don't worry.
You're out of the line
of fire for the moment.
She's too busy
torturing Janel and Miles.
Miles?
Oh, your friend.
They found him?
He's fine.
Great.
That's great, Zee.
Does that mean you're leaving?
Not right away.
Let's talk about you.
More specifically,
about what you did last night.
What can I say?
I get drunk,
I become an art critic.
Do you regret what you did?
Not really.
I never liked
those pieces anyway.
So, what are you feeling?
I'm feeling like I don't want
to be analyzed by my sister.
Sorry.
It's what I do.
This situation is
not that complex, Zee.
I am wallowing in self-pity
and acting out my frustrations
by throwing tantrums.
All right, Dr. Norvo.
If that's your diagnosis,
what's your prescription?
Mother disapproves of suicide...
all that blood on the carpets.
Not funny.
Best I can do with a hangover.
Norvo...
what would happen if you
left with me tomorrow?
What do you mean?
I mean, what would happen
if you went back
to Deep Space 9 with me?
Mother would go insane.
Forget about her for the moment.
I can't... I can't
just pick up and leave.
Well, it doesn't have
to be a permanent move.
Think of it as a vacation...
a break from all of this
some time to clear your head,
that's all.
I... I don't know
if I can leave all of this
on Janel's shoulders.
Janel can handle it.
It's not that simple.
There are some things
going on that are complicated.
Like what?
Things with the company.
No offense, Norvo
but you're not exactly holding
the company together.
Mother can pay a real accountant
to do the work she's given you.
I don't... I don't know, Zee.
Well, think about it.
You're right.
The problem's definitely
in the secondary
input transtator.
But the transtator
checks out perfectly.
I'm sure it does
but it's the wrong
transtator for this drill.
What?
You need a 52-J.
This is a 52-L.
It says 52-J.
I know,
but it's definitely an "L."
Must have been
accidentally mislabeled.
Or deliberately.
Another equipment failure?
Perhaps if you hadn't
dismissed Mr. Lorkin
this wouldn't have happened.
He was dismissed
on my mother's personal order.
Then we'll have to find a way
of changing her mind, won't we?
Who's your new mechanic, Janel?
This is Mr. O'Brien.
He's a friend of the family.
That wouldn't be Chief O'Brien,
would it?
How did you know that?
I have several friends
in the New Sydney police.
I heard they recently rescued
a Starfleet Chief named O'Brien
from an unpleasant situation.
That's me.
I don't believe
I caught your name.
Thadial Bokar.
I'm a commodities broker
attempting to establish
business ties
with the illustrious
Tigan family.
Will you excuse us
for a moment, Chief?
Mr. Bokar and I have
some business to discuss.
Thank you for your help.
I'll have a new transtator
installed right away.
Glad to do it.
Sabotaging our drills isn't
going to convince me
to do more business
with the Orion Syndicate.
We'll argue about that later.
We have more immediate concerns.
O'Brien is with
Starfleet Intelligence.
No, he isn't.
He works with my sister
on Deep Space 9.
That may be what
he wants you to think
but why was he on New Sydney
trying to infiltrate
the Syndicate?
He was looking for some woman.
"Some woman."
Do you know the name
of this woman?
No.
Well, I do.
Her name was Morica Bilby.
What?
Now, of course, I haven't heard
from Morica Bilby
in quite some time.
Rumor has it that she's dead,
but I wouldn't know anything
about that.
What I do know
is that Chief O'Brien
should leave this system quickly
before something happens to him.
So, you're not leaving
until tomorrow?
Well, probably.
It really depends on Ezri.
Why?
Well, she's my superior officer.
I go when she goes.
Besides, I'm not looking forward
to seeing Captain Sisko.
He has a boot
with my name on it.
This isn't a good time
for guests.
There's a lot of work to do.
The quicker you're on your way,
the better.
Your brother seems eager
to get rid of us.
Oh, don't mind him.
He's been under
a lot of pressure.
Do you know a man
named Thadial Bokar?
Says he's a commodities broker.
No.
But I make it a point
to know as little as possible
about the family business.
Why?
Well, he came to the mine
to talk with Janel
while I was working
on the drill.
There was something about him
reminded me of when I was
working undercover
with the Orion Syndicate...
you know,
something about the way
they dealt with civilians.
You think this Mr. Bokar
is a member of the Syndicate?
It's just a feeling...
and a pretty strong feeling.
We should tell Janel.
I think Janel already knows.
Well, I know
I'm not offering you
any hard evidence here,
Lieutenant
but your brother seems
like a man
who's being pressured
by the Syndicate.
He's experiencing
sudden equipment breakdowns
work stoppages,
mysterious accidents.
That's the way the Syndicate
extorts money
from legitimate companies.
"Do business with us
or we'll ruin you."
Janel is not someone
who's easily intimidated
and my mother... she would burn
this place to the ground
before she did business
with the Syndicate.
Well, there's one way
to find out.
Do you have access to
the company's financial records?
What would you do
on Deep Space 9?
Take a vacation.
Clear my head.
Clear your head of what?
I-I don't know.
Then why do you need
a vacation?
I guess I don't, really.
I just... but it would be nice
to spend some time with Ezri.
You're spending time
with her right now, aren't you?
Yes...
We're ready to open 25 Beta.
I'll be right there.
Norvo, this is a very bad time
for you to take a vacation.
We have far too much work to do.
Have you finished the review?
Almost.
Well, then maybe
you should get to it.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's go.
Now I remember why I never went
into the family business...
all these contracts and invoices
balance sheets
and shipping orders.
Oh...
I feel like I'm trapped
in some kind
of Ferengi nightmare.
What?
What is it?
I don't know.
What's going on here?
What do you mean?
Did you come here to find me
or to prevent me
finding out the truth?
I don't know
what you're talking about
so maybe
you should just tell me, Chief.
The connection between
the Orion Syndicate
and your family...
is Morica Bilby.
She was on the company's
payroll when she died.
Did you know about this?
No. Of course not.
Well, someone
in your family did.
And since they didn't mention it
they obviously
don't want us to know.
Are you suggesting?
I'm not suggesting anything
but you have to face
the possibility
that somebody in your family...
was involved in her death.
There.
Nine months ago.
Morica Bilby shows up
on the payroll
as a shipping consultant.
Five bars of latinum
a week for services rendered.
What services?
There's no cross-reference.
No indication of what she
was doing for the company.
Whatever it was, she must
have been good at the job.
Look here.
Her salary increases
to ten bars a week
then 20, then 30.
The last payment entry
was six weeks ago.
The day before she was killed.
Who's in charge of the payroll?
My mother... ultimately,
but she's turned over
most of the day-to-day
operations to Janel
and Norvo's been doing
the bookkeeping.
Any one of them could know
about Morica's payments.
Or all of them.
Lieutenant, we have to show this
to the authorities
on New Sydney.
Not yet.
Not until I find out
what's happened.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Why was this woman
on our payroll?
We were returning a favor.
To whom?
To the Orion Syndicate.
And what "favor"
did they do for us?
Remember when the Ferengi
opened up the Timor II mine
and there was a ten point drop
in the price of pergium?
Well, that came
at a bad moment.
We were overextended
on some loans
our cash reserves were depleted
and a Jem'Hadar raid
destroyed an entire shipment
before it reached the refinery
on Rigel IV.
So you turned to the Syndicate?
They came to me.
They offered us a way out
and I took it.
I did what I had to do.
And I don't remember
you asking a lot of questions
when our cash problems
were resolved overnight.
Because I trusted you.
Obviously, it was a mistake.
What about Morica?
About a month after
Bokar arranged the loan
he came to me and said
it was time to return the favor.
There was a woman
who needed a job
with a salary
but without
any actual work involved.
He said she was the widow
of one of their associates
and they needed
to take care of her.
I didn't feel like
I was in a position to say no
so I started
making the payments.
No one would have been the wiser
if Norvo had altered
the payroll records
like I asked him.
You dragged your little brother
into this?
You're the one who says
there's nothing more important
than the company.
Well, that's all
I was thinking about...
the company.
You dumped it in my lap
and I saved it
so don't start complaining now.
If it weren't for me,
we would have been finished.
Don't you rationalize
what you've done.
All right, all right.
We can talk
about who saved what later.
Right now,
we have to concentrate
on what happened to Morica.
The payroll records show
a steady increase
in her payments.
Why?
She wasn't happy
with her salary.
She said the Syndicate promised
her a comfortable living
and she wasn't comfortable
on what we were paying her.
How did she die?
I don't know.
Janel... if you have anything
to do with this
now is the time to speak.
What are you saying?
That I had her killed?
I'm asking.
Mother, he wouldn't
have killed her.
You stay out of this.
Listen to me.
I will get you the very best
solicitor in New Sydney
but you must tell me the truth.
I didn't kill her.
Oh, Janel,
why don't I believe you?
Why don't I believe
that this woman
just happened to die
at the exact moment
she was pressuring you
for more money?
Why won't you listen to him?
He didn't do it.
I may not have shed any tears
when I found out she was dead
but I didn't kill her.
Then who did?
The police said...
Norvo, you don't know what
happened to Morica, do you?
Even if it was an accident,
we are going to hire...
I'm the idiot brother.
How would I know?
Tell me you don't know
anything about this.
I tried to reason with her
but she was very angry...
angry at the Syndicate,
angry at us
even angry at her husband
for getting himself killed.
I didn't go there
to kill her, see?
I really didn't
but she wouldn't listen to me.
She started yelling.
Said that our family was
just as bad as the Syndicate
that we were all liars
and cheats.
And then, suddenly I realized
that if she were dead...
all of our problems
would go away.
Oh, Norvo.
I took care of it.
You always said that I was
too weak...
to handle the tough ones.
I'm not.
I proved it.
I handled a problem
that you couldn't.
I handled it.
I need to, uh...
inspect the ore
samples from 53-C.
We have to make a decision
on whether to open up a new...
Janel, forget about the mine.
It doesn't matter.
I want you to listen to me.
After Norvo's trial is over,
you need to go.
Go where?
It doesn't matter.
Just go.
Find another life for yourself.
Trust me.
You'll be happier.
They've taken Norvo.
I'm going to stay on New Sydney
for the trial
and then I'm going
to head back to Deep Space 9.
This isn't my fault,
is it, Ezri?
I didn't do this, did I?
Mind if I join you?
When did you get back?
Last night.
Norvo was sentenced
to 30 years.
I wish I could say
I was sorry, but...
considering what he did,
he got off easy.
I understand
why you feel that way
but you didn't know him, Miles.
Norvo was very gifted.
When we were young,
he had so much potential.
Norvo was always the one
that we all thought
would be something special
and I don't know what happened.
I don't know
how my brother turned into...
You know, I guess
I just spent so many years
dreaming of ways
to get out of that house
that I didn't see
what was really going on inside
what was happening to Norvo...
the endless humiliation
the constant drumbeat
of criticism...
the way his heart was carved up
into little pieces.
I should have seen it.
I should have tried
to stop it.
You can't blame yourself.
You're not responsible for that.
But I am, don't you see?
I should have gone home
a long time ago.