Have you ever seen anything
so disgusting?
The way he's undressing her
with his eyes.
And look at his hands!
What about his hands?
His gestures--
they're obscene.
You should arrest him.
You're joking.
He's pitiful.
Doesn't he realize she loves me?
I don't think he does.
To be honest,
I don't think she does, either.
Thanks for your support.
Brother,
I just talked to Moogie.
She says Grand Nagus Zek
has disappeared.
What do you mean, disappeared?
He left her a note
saying he was going
on a business safari
to open new territories
for financial
exploitation.
That's our Nagus.
He said he'd be back
in five days.
That was 12 days ago.
Twelve?
Has he done this before?
Not for this long.
Moogie did some checking.
No one's heard from him.
He could be hurt
or even dead.
We have to do something!
He probably stopped
off on Risa
you know, for a little rest
and relaxation.
Risa? With all those
gorgeous women?
He wouldn't
do that to Moogie.
Have you looked
at our mother lately?
She's not getting
any younger.
Now, do us both a favor
and stop worrying about Zek.
He'll show up.
Are you sure?
Good-bye, Rom.
Good-bye.
Where'd Ezri go?
Oh, uh, she slipped out the back
with Bashir.
They left together?
Mm-hmm.
I think they were
holding... hands.
Oh.
Blessed Exchequer,
whose greed is eternal.
Allow this humble bribe
to open your ears
and hear this plea
from your most devout debtor.
Continue to bless my bar
with a steady stream
of thirsty customers
whose pockets are lined
with latinum
and whose skills at dabo
are shaky at best...
and while you're at it...
...see if you can do something
about Dr. Bashir.
Don't hurt him or anything.
Just get him off the station
for a couple of months.
( chuckles )
Oh, and one other thing.
I opened negotiations
with Ezri three months ago
but I can't seem
to close the deal.
Anything you can do to help...
( door chimes )
Come in.
Ezri.
( squeals in pain )
Anyone else here?
Just you and me.
( groans )
Is that
the bedroom?
I owe you.
Oh!
Does it have
to be so rough
the first time?
( gasps )
I don't know what you think is
going on here, but think again.
Don't tell me, um...
This is some new
kind of therapy?
Am I supposed to start talking
about my childhood or something?
I hope not.
Good, because I'd
rather talk about us.
Dax... Dax, you're
the most fascinating
woman I've ever met.
I love you.
There, I said it.
My name's not Dax.
Oh, I-I get it.
Your clothes, the knife,
this aggressive attitude--
it's all role-playing.
Call me Shmun.
Shmun?
Yeah.
And I'll call you T'lana--
you know, from "Vulcan
Love Slave," Volume III.
You're a very confused man,
aren't you?
If your friend Zek
is depending on you
he's in a lot more trouble
than he thinks.
Zek? What does he have
to do with any of this?
I'll let him explain.
Hello, Quark.
It's me, your Grand Nagus.
You'll never guess where I am.
Risa?
If you said Risa, guess again.
I'm in the alternate universe.
You're probably wondering...
You're not my Dax.
You're from over there.
You're catching on.
Oh...
You see,
I'm in a bit of trouble.
I'm being held prisoner
by the Alliance
and I'm going to need you
to help me regain my freedom.
The Regent said
he would send me home
in exchange
for a ship's cloaking device.
They don't have them
in this universe.
I wish I'd known that
before I got here.
I could have saved myself
a lot of aggravation
and made a nice profit
at the same time.
Oh, well...
My fate is in your hands, Quark.
I need a cloaking device
and I need it now.
You're the only one
I can count on.
If you do this for me, I promise
I'll be eternally grateful.
And don't forget
to tell your mother I love her.
Good-bye.
He should have
gone to Risa.
The Regent wants the cloaking
device in three days.
That's not much time.
Cloaking technology isn't
that easy to come by.
You'll find a way.
And if I don't?
The Nagus will die.
( sighing ):
Oh.
ROM:
Anyone out there?
Not that I can see.
Then let's do it.
QUARK:
All right-- together now.
( straining ):
Now, lift!
ROM:
It's heavy.
QUARK:
Oh, I noticed.
Watch the steps.
I see them, Brother.
I told you, cloaking
the cloaking device
was a good idea.
Brilliant, but couldn't
you have done something
about its weight?
Uh... nope, but if it makes
you feel any better
the cloaking device
on the Defiant is a lot heavier.
Tell it to my hernia.
You know what's bothering me?
It seems wrong to be stealing
a cloaking device
for the Alliance.
We're not stealing
it for them.
We're stealing
it to save Zek.
But what about
this other Ezri?
She's a Trill.
So?
So, shouldn't she
be with the rebels
fighting against
the Alliance?
Be sure to point that
out when you meet her.
Just don't forget,
she carries a knife.
Shh.
Someone's coming.
Set it down, quick.
Oh!
( voices approaching )
Act normal.
I'm telling you,
Captain
we have to find a way
to expand our lines
beyond the Kalandra system.
SISKO:
I agree.
If we don't move soon
the ionic storms
will isolate our position.
And allow the Dominion
to flank us.
Is something wrong, gentlemen?
It's the bulkhead.
What about it?
Rom's thinking of painting
his quarters this color.
They're already
that color.
I told you.
No wonder I like it.
It's a very soothing
shade of gray.
I'm glad you approve.
Captain...
Hmm?
Carry on.
SISKO:
I'll talk to Admiral Ross.
MARTOK:
I'll talk to Chancellor Gowron
as well.
They're headed
for the Klingon ship.
What if they discover
the cloaking device is missing?
Let's get out of here.
Where is it?
I'm not sure.
Well, find it.
Ow! Oh!
Good job, Brother.
But I wouldn't touch those
induction coils if I were you.
Thanks for the warning.
Up we go.
Come on, Ezri's waiting
for us in Cargo Bay 14.
QUARK:
One Klingon cloaking device
as requested.
As soon as I bring
that to the Regent
he'll release Zek.
Then what happens?
Then you get him back.
Would you stop doing that?
Doing what?
Staring at me.
Sorry, but you look
just like our Ezri
except you're a lot taller.
What are you talking about?
She's exactly the same height.
Uh, I don't think so.
Don't be an idiot.
I'm telling you,
they're identical... I think.
Do I have to throw you
off this transport pad?
One thing's for sure--
their personalities
aren't identical.
How do we know the Regent
will keep his word
and send Zek
back to us?
You don't.
But there's not much
you can do about it, is there?
Yes, there is.
Brother, I think
we should go with her.
I don't think you'll like it
too much on the other side.
That, I believe.
But my idiot
brother is right.
We're coming with you.
MARTOK:
Ferengi!
I'll have you
hanging by your ears.
Well, what are we
waiting for?
ROM:
It didn't work.
Yes, it did.
We're on Terok Nor.
It looks like Deep
Space 9 to me.
I suppose a cargo bay
is a cargo bay
no matter what universe
you're in.
But this is an
alternate universe.
Shouldn't everything
be different?
It's different enough.
Remember what Captain
Sisko once told us--
in this universe,
we're both dead.
That's so sad.
I would have liked
to meet myself.
We better get moving.
I've got a ship waiting for us
on Landing Pad C.
What's the rush?
This is a rebel base
and we're working
for the Alliance.
Vic?
I thought you two were dead.
We are!
You're not a hologram.
A what?
Throw down your phasers,
Fontaine.
I'll see you in hell first.
( yells )
I can't believe it.
Julian just shot
Vic Fontaine.
I thought
Vic was his favorite singer.
No wonder they call it
the alternate universe.
You, behind the crates!
You can come out now.
Do as he says.
Well, well,
well...
look who we
have here.
I'll bet you're
surprised to see us
but I can explain.
You worthless
piece of space trash.
Don't hurt her!
( groaning )
Hey, you're supposed
to be the good guys!
My mistake.
SMILEY:
I'm sorry, Rom, but that
cloaking device of yours
is now the property of the
Terran Resistance Forces.
But you don't understand.
You have to give us back
the cloaking device.
We need it
to rescue the Nagus.
That's not who you should
be worried about right now.
Do you know what we do
to Alliance sympathizers?
Give it a rest,
Julian.
I'll give it a rest
just as soon as
these three
get what's
coming to them.
I don't know about you,
but I like our Bashir better.
SMILEY:
You have to forgive him.
He's had a rough
go of it lately.
He lost a close friend
in a skirmish
with Alliance troops.
This has nothing
to do with Jadzia.
Do you know what
would happen to us
if the Alliance got hold
of a cloaking device?
SMILEY:
It wouldn't be pretty.
They'd wipe us out
in a matter of weeks.
Besides, there's nothing I
loathe more than traitors.
I'm not a traitor.
She's right.
You have to believe in something
before you can betray it.
I believe in getting paid
for my work
and you still owe me
for the last job I did for you.
We're fighting
for our freedom here--
for our very lives--
and all you care about is money?
Like you said, you have
to have something to believe in.
Let me ram those words
down her throat.
You're forgetting something,
Julian.
The Alliance didn't get
the cloaking device-- we did
and that gives us the edge--
and we have
these gentlemen
to thank for it.
So what do you want to do--
give them medals?
I don't think
their Captain Sisko
would be too pleased to
know they were over here
interfering
in our affairs.
That's why we
didn't tell him.
Huh. Thought as much.
I say we send them back
to where they belong--
let Sisko deal with them.
We can't go back...
not without Zek.
The way I see it,
you've got two choices.
You can either head back
to where you came from
or you can head
for Alliance territory
and try to rescue your friend
without the cloaking device.
You have
till morning to decide.
Either way...
you're staying with us.
Tough break.
I'll live.
Are you sure?
( sighs )
Don't worry about me.
Smiley's right about one thing--
if you're found
in Alliance territory
without the cloaking device,
you're dead.
Are you suggesting we
should go back home?
It's the smart move.
Do we look
smart to you?
You have such nimble fingers,
my dear.
( chuckling )
How many times
have I heard that?
I don't think
I could survive
this incarceration
without them.
Oh, I'm glad to be of help.
I only wish I could
return the favor.
After all, you've
been suffering here
for a lot longer
than I have.
It hasn't been too bad.
I always find a way
of amusing myself
and besides,
when your people
give the Regent
the cloaking device
we'll both be free.
If Quark and Rom
don't screw things up.
( screams )
( blow lands, grunting )
INTENDANT:
Have a seat, big boy.
( whimpers )
You told me your people could
deliver the cloaking device.
You guaranteed it!
Well, so I said,
and so they shall.
Well, then we have
nothing to worry about.
( laughing )
Oh... so fragile.
Ah.
That's quite a temper
you have, my dear.
Mmm. It's one
of my best features.
Now, where were we?
Mind going back to tugging
at my ear hairs?
Mmm...
your wish is my command.
( giggling )
We have to find
a way out of here.
And then?
And then we get our hands
on the cloaking device
and finish what we started.
All right. Let's say
you manage to save
this Grand Nagus
of yours...
then what?
Then we go home...
and never come
back here again.
That's it?
Isn't it enough?
Quark, don't play dumb with me.
You're risking your life
for him.
There has to be a reason for it.
He's the Nagus,
he's the man my mother loves
not to mention, he's the head
of the Ferengi Alliance.
In other words, he's rich.
( chuckling )
They don't come any richer.
I see.
How much are you expecting
to get out of him?
Knowing the Nagus,
I'd say...
a pat on the head
and a fistful of empty promises.
I don't understand.
There's nothing to understand.
He's my Nagus...
and when your Nagus
gets in trouble
you're supposed
to do something about it.
Why?
I don't know.
Loyalty?
You're kidding me, right?
You're doing this
out of loyalty?
Would you stop looking
at me like that?
You're making me feel
like an idiot.
EZRI:
I hope so.
Brother...
I just realized something.
This should be good.
This is supposed to be
an alternate universe
but their Captain O'Brien seems
as nice as our Chief O'Brien.
So?
Don't you see?
It doesn't make any sense.
It's not "alternate."
Go back to sleep, Rom.
Right...
but it's all very confusing.
( phaser fire )
What was that?
How would I know?
ROM:
Brother, look out!
It's Brunt!
QUARK:
I don't think
it's our Brunt.
What took
you so long?
Sorry.
Been a little busy.
I had to break
into the cargo bay
steal back the cloaking
device you lost
and get it into our ship.
But on top of that...
Okay, quit your
complaining
and get us
out of here.
I'm... working on it.
Aah...
You two must be hungry.
I've got food and drink
waiting for you
on the ship.
He's so nice.
Scary, isn't it?
( low engine rumble )
What was that?
Brunt modified
the dilithium matrix
to maximize the output.
He did, did he?
He's a very
good engineer.
He's also
a very good cook.
These fried tube grubs
are dee-licious.
Better hope
he didn't poison them.
( chuckling )
Mmm...
maybe in our universe,
he'd do something like that--
but not over here.
Over here, everything's...
alternate.
So he's a nice guy.
Which means the tube grubs here
should be poisonous
because they're not
poisonous on our side.
But if Brunt
gave us poisonous
tube grubs...
it would mean he wasn't as nice
as we think he is
but he has to be nice
because our Brunt isn't.
Rom you're driving
me crazy.
It's not me, Brother.
It's this alternate universe.
It just doesn't
make any sense.
More tube grubs?
Yes, please.
No.
Yes!
Oh, no.
In case you get hungry.
I put a cup of hot tea
by your bunk.
You should get some rest.
( groaning )
It has been a long day.
( yawns )
You're telling me.
We're not due
to rendezvous
with the Regent's ship
for another 46 hours.
I'll wake you
long before that.
( laughing )
I'd like to see the look
on Bashir's face
when he discovers
we've stolen back
the cloaking device.
You think he and Smiley
will come after us?
Oh, they can't
let the Regent
get his hands
on that technology.
Sounds like your sympathies
are with the rebels.
I hate the Alliance.
Then why help them get
the cloaking device?
Ezri and I are partners.
More than that--
she's...
the closest friend
I've ever had.
And how close is that?
Not as close as I'd like.
Too bad.
I'm not her type.
And I don't think you are,
either.
What makes you say that?
Let's just say that
when it comes to men, she's...
very particular.
( sneezing loudly )
Interesting.
My sinuses are clear
for the first time in years.
See if this Ferengi has any more
of this... beetle snuff.
Certainly. But
first, my Regent
I must talk to you
about the Intendant.
It's taken us
over two years
to track down that
treacherous wench.
We should eliminate her
and be done with it.
I will deal with
the Intendant
in my own way and
in my own time
but first, I want
that cloaking device!
Yes.
Think of it--
with a fleet of
cloaked ships
I will be able to crush
the rebellion once and for all!
And then, we can
kill the Intendant.
We will see.
ROM:
Big ship.
How do we know we
can trust the Regent?
Once he has the
cloaking device
there's nothing to stop
him from killing us all.
It's a little late
to back out now, Quark.
By bringing him
the cloaking device
you've proven yourself useful.
Believe me
the Regent never gets rid
of anyone he finds useful.
I hope you're right.
Me, too.
You-- come here.
Your Regent needs you.
Nice fit.
Our visitors from the other
universe have arrived
and I'm happy to report
they have not come
empty-handed.
Look who the Regent is.
So?
So who's president
of the Federation? Gul Dukat?
They don't have
a Federation here.
Is there a problem,
Ferengi?
Just ignore him.
Now...
if you'll give us the Nagus,
we'll be on our way
and you can go on with your
plans for mass destruction
genocide and all those
other good things.
Victory is finally
within my grasp.
I want this operational
within the hour.
And it will be so,
Exalted One.
We have a deal, right?
Do we?
Tell him.
INTENDANT:
Yes, my dear...
why don't you tell him?
( quiet chuckle )
I knew you wouldn't
disappoint me.
Uh-oh.
You're not going to give
us the Nagus, are you?
You...
you knew about
this all along.
What can I say?
I'm loyal to my friends.
Isn't she just
the best?
I don't understand--
you're letting her go?
She earned it.
Having them bring us the
cloaking device was her idea.
Get rid of these two.
Is that really necessary?
They could come in handy.
If the Regent
wants your opinion
he'll ask for it.
Do not kill them just yet.
But Your Magnificence...
You heard me!
Lock them up.
Let's go.
I hope you two are
very happy together.
We will be.
Our Ezri would never betray us,
which means...
Oh, don't start
with that again.
Right...
Rom, you're not going
to tell your mother
about the Intendant
and me, are you?
It would break
her heart.
In a million pieces.
You see,
she worships me...
and I worship her
right back.
Besides, this is
all your fault.
If it weren't for you,
I never would have
been able
to get to this universe.
You remember the last time
you came home
to visit your mother?
Well, one night
while you were sleeping,
I got up to get
a bite to eat.
And there
on the kitchen table,
was a Starfleet padd.
My... engineering notebook?
With the schematics
for the multidimensional
transporter
that Chief O'Brien
gave me to study.
You stole it!
I'm your Nagus.
You have no secrets from me.
I still don't understand
why you'd want to come here
in the first place.
Simple, really.
I came to find new
financial opportunities
for the Ferengi people.
In the alternate
universe?!
Well... it seemed like
a good idea at the time.
Right now
it would be a good idea
for us to find a way
out of here.
I just don't feel right
about this.
Quark and Rom
deserve better.
Forget about them,
all right?
That's just it--
I can't.
I like them...
and so do you.
Don't tell me
who I like.
Talk to the Intendant--
she listens to you.
Tell her the Ferengi
kept their part of the bargain.
We should do the same.
What a novel idea.
Now, I can't
remember
the last time I kept my word.
Maybe now's a good time
to start.
Forget it, Brunt.
No, not this time.
That's all right.
Let him talk, my dear.
He obviously feels
very passionately
about this
and you know how responsive
I am to passion.
Go on.
What do we gain
from their death?
Nothing.
On the other hand,
if we let them live
they may come in handy.
I never thought
of that.
The Regent will
give them to you.
All you have to do is ask.
Maybe...
but why waste a favor on
those two little trolls?
No, I'm afraid
I don't much care
for your suggestion
and as a matter
of fact...
I don't much
like you, either.
( groans )
No!
He was going
to betray me.
I could see it
in his eyes.
You wouldn't do that
to me, would you?
Would you?!
Oh... oh, oh, oh, no.
No. No, of course
you wouldn't.
( sighing )
I...
I've suffered so many
disappointments
in my life--
Brunt...
Sisko, Bareil...
the list goes
on and on.
( sighs )
Dispose of that,
would you?
It depresses me.
It's your mess.
You clean it up.
She's not afraid of anyone,
is she?
Not even me.
Regent, long-range sensors
have detected an enemy ship.
It's the Defiant.
Excellent!
It is time to test
the cloaking device.
Um, I'm afraid
it's not yet operational.
And why is that?
Well, it's a very complicated
piece of equipment.
One of the Ferengi
seemed to know
how it worked.
Then why is he not here?
I'll get him.
Getting the cloaking
device on line?
That's simple.
Good.
Lower the force field.
QUARK:
Hold on a second.
Why should we help
the Regent?
Or you, for that matter?
I'm trying
to save your lives.
That's a very
worthy goal!
Since when do you care
about what happens to us?
All right, forget it.
I don't want
to forget it.
I'm sorry, Brother.
Maybe you want to die in this
crazy, mixed-up universe
but I don't.
Neither do I!
Lower the force field.
I suppose we have
nothing to lose.
Where do you think
you're going?
With him-- he
needs my help.
You're a bartender, Quark.
What are you going to do,
mix him a drink?
Don't worry,
Brother.
I'm not thirsty.
I don't expect you
to believe this
but I am trying
to help you.
You're right!
I don't believe you.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Isodine coupler.
Does this look like
an isodine coupler to you?
I don't see how anything
gets fixed around here!
I'd advise you
to watch your tone
of voice, Ferengi!
Or what?
You won't let me install
the cloaking device?!
I'm... sorry if
I've upset you.
Now, will you please
get back to work?
Don't mind if I do.
( whispering )
Oh.
Really?
Absolutely.
I have never
tried that before.
Few man have,
but I think
you'll find it
very stimulating.
What do you expect
in return?
Terok Nor,
of course.
I was planning on
destroying that station.
Plans can
be changed.
I will consider it.
What more
can I ask?
ROM:
Uh...
( singsongy ):
Mr. Regent...
What is it?
Your cloak is ready.
Ah.
GARAK:
I'll take over from here.
It's working.
Well done.
INTENDANT:
You mean, no one
can see us?
How deliciously
deceitful.
Are you certain you
know how to operate
the device?
Well, what I don't know,
I always can learn.
ROM:
It's pretty simple
once you understand the basics.
Now... what about my brother
and the Nagus?
Do we have any
further use for them?
Not that I
can think of.
Then get rid of them.
You mean, we're going home?
No.
He means you're
going to die.
That settles it!
I'm never helping
you again!
Or anyone else,
for that matter.
Come along, now.
I'm really beginning
to hate this universe.
GARAK:
What we have here,
gentlemen
is 10cc's of concentrated
Ulcartic virus.
It's very deadly
and quite painful.
It elevates the temperature
of your body
heating your internal organs
until they literally boil.
I was hoping
to use this
on the Intendant,
but I suppose
I'll have to settle
for the for the four of you.
Now...
who would like to go first?
I'm waiting.
( chuckles )
Why don't you give us
a couple of days
to think it over
and we'll get back to you.
All right, then,
I'll pick.
Let's see...
What an amateur.
Excuse me?
I mean, compared
to our Garak.
Now that man knows
how to conduct
an interrogation.
I'm not interrogating anyone.
ZEK:
Why not?
Did it ever occur to you
that we may know things
that you could use
to your advantage?
Like what?
We're not going to tell you--
not unless you
interrogate us.
I don't have time for this.
I want to be on the Bridge
when we destroy the Defiant.
In our universe,
work comes before pleasure.
Our Garak
would have us hanging
by our toenails by now
telling him
all our secrets.
What secrets?
That's for us to know
and you to find out.
If you were smart
you'd cross over
to our universe
and get some pointers
from our Garak.
When it comes
to torture
assassination
and sabotage
you could learn
a lot from him.
I know all there is
to know about sabotage.
( laughing )
That's not what we hear.
Something's wrong.
We should have caught
that Ferengi ship long ago.
We'll find them.
For all we know
the Regent may already
have the cloaking device.
In fact, he might have us
in his sights right now
and we wouldn't
even know it.
Don't start getting
paranoid, Smiley.
Even if the Regent
has the cloaking device
chances are,
it isn't functional yet.
I hope you're right.
They have no idea
that we are behind them.
There's nothing I enjoy
better than a good ambush.
It is time.
I don't understand.
Is this Garak of yours
an assassin
or a tailor?
An assassin.
Both.
Tailor.
Never mind.
I have to be back on the Bridge.
Now...
who's first?
Drop the cloak!
I hate it
when you're right.
Evasive action-- now!
Fire!
What was that?
Sabotage--
what else?
( hostile hissing )
( yelling )
We've experienced
primary system
failure.
That Ferengi,
he did this!
I'm unable
to get anything back on line.
( frustrated grunting )
( yelling )
You taught me
something
about sabotage, and now
I'm going to teach you
something about pain.
( groaning )
( laughing )
( yells )
( moaning )
( breathing heavily )
How much is this
going to cost us?
I'm not doing this
for money.
Then why?
Do you want to get out
of here or not?
Of course we do.
Then stop asking questions
and let's go.
They're not coming
after us.
Why not?
They can't.
Their power grid's off-line.
( chuckles )
Then what do you say
we give the Regent
a proper greeting?
Reversing course.
We must raise shields!
We can't!
I don't know how much more of
this the hull can withstand.
HELMSMAN:
Captain O'Brien
would like
to have a word with you.
O'BRIEN:
That's a nice ship you have
Regent.
I'd hate to see it destroyed.
But, of course,
if you insist...
( sighs )
What are your terms?
Ooh, a simple
unconditional surrender
should do the trick.
INTENDANT:
I'm afraid
you've run out of options.
Victory is yours.
( chuckling )
Prepare to be boarded.
WORF:
I have been betrayed.
I knew I should have killed
those two Ferengi
the moment they came aboard.
( frustrated grunting )
What a surprise.
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Here I am.
Is that really necessary?
I was about to ask you
the same question.
Ah.
( laughs )
That's better.
You and I have to get
to one of the escape shuttles.
You go.
I'm staying here.
You can't be serious.
You shouldn't
have killed Brunt.
Isn't it a little late
to be developing a conscience?
I hope not.
Brunt's dead?
Sorry...
wrong Brunt.
We're not going to let
her get away, are we?
I owe her that much.
Oh, let her go.
There's something
about that woman
I find intoxicating.
( cheering )
ROM:
Glad to be
going home?
You bet I am.
That doesn't mean
I won't be coming back.
Here?
What for?
There's a fortune to be made
in the alternate universe.
I can feel it in my lobes.
Well, don't
expect us
to come chasing
after you again.
Oh, no, I won't.
( laughs ):
Next time, I'll bring you
along with me.
In that case
I won't bother
saying good-bye.
You know...
coming back here
isn't such a bad idea...
if I knew I could see you again.
I'm not going anywhere.
I could stick around
a couple of days.
You could show me the station.
I don't think
that's such a good idea.
I could help you work
on that conscience of yours.
I think I can take it from here.
Excuse me.
Leeta?
Do I know you?
We're married!
( incredulous
chuckle )
I don't think so.
You're Ezri, right?
Captain Smiley wants
me to debrief you.
Must be my lucky day.
This is quite
a fascinating place
don't you agree?
I want to go home.
Me, too.