Well, listen up, listen up.
To Lieutenant Hector Ilario...
living proof that Starfleet
Academy produces the finest
fighter pilots in the galaxy...
- Hear, hear.
- I haven't finished yet.
Don't ruin it, Julian.
That's just what
a toast should be...
short and to the point.
I wouldn't mind hearing
a little more.
Now, now...
modesty above all.
This is no time to be modest.
This man...
this youth, this mere pup
still wet behind the ears...
I'm 22.
I was speaking metaphorically.
This inspired cherub
masterfully piloted
the Defiant into battle
against a half a dozen
Jem'Hadar attack ships
and once
all the smoke had cleared
only one ship remained intact
and that, ladies and gentlemen
was the USS Defiant.
The kid's a born helmsman.
And so say all of us.
Hear, hear!
Well, thanks.
I'm just glad to be here.
It's the best posting
in the galaxy.
If there's anything you want...
anything at all... just ask.
Well, there is one thing.
Name it.
Next time you two go
to the holosuite
I'd like to come along.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
Can't be done.
No. It's out of the question.
It's impossible.
Don't take it personally.
They're very serious about
their leisure activities.
It's a good way
to relieve stress.
Yeah. I highly recommend it.
Just not with us.
Yeah. You know, when you
have a holosuite visit
it's sort of a
personal experience.
He's very particular
about anybody seeing
him in his coonskin cap.
You understand.
I suppose.
Gentlemen,
your holosuite is ready.
Terrific.
Now, if there's
anything else you need...
Just let us know.
Have you ever gone to
the holosuite with them?
Me?
Never.
Huh.
I know when I'm not wanted.
To the class of '72.
Another round?
- No.
Time to go?
It was time to go
about an hour ago.
Okay.
Oh, oh, okay.
We'll get you home.
I'll take him.
His quarters are on my way.
You sure?
He won't be
the first drunken Ensign
I've escorted home.
Someday, remind me to tell you
about a bar on Bolarus
and a certain young Mr. Sisko.
This way.
I never had real
Saurian brandy before.
It's Captain Sisko's favorite.
It kind of sneaks up
on you, doesn't it?
Speaking of sneaking up
on you...
here we are... home sweet home.
You all right?
Do you want some raktajino?
I'm fine. Fine.
I wish they could
have been there.
They would've loved it.
To see me fly
the Defiant into battle.
It was incredible.
I should get going.
Make sure you get some sleep.
You know something, Lieutenant?
You're very beautiful.
And you're very drunk.
True enough
but in the morning,
I'll be sober
and you'll still be beautiful.
Good night, Ilario.
Good night, Lieutenant.
The time is 0600 hours.
The time is 0600 hours
and ten seconds.
Yeah, yeah. I'm up.
Fanalian tea. Hot.
Full security alert.
Yes, sir.
Get everybody back.
Hurry up.
What happened?
Lieutenant Ilario
has been killed.
Killed?
How?
It appears someone shot him.
He was killed by what appears
to be some kind
of chemically propelled
projectile weapon.
A gun?
Dr. Bashir recovered
a single tritanium bullet
from Ilario's chest.
He was shot through the heart.
You don't see one of those
every day.
Nobody uses projectile
weapons anymore.
You said this is tritanium,
right?
That's correct.
Chief, did you ever hear
of a TR-116 rifle?
It was a prototype
developed by Starfleet Security
to operate in
energy dampening fields
or radiogenic environments.
That's right.
Anywhere where a normal phaser
would be useless.
If I'm not mistaken,
the TR-116 rifle fired
a chemically propelled
tritanium bullet.
You say a prototype.
Were they ever mass-produced?
No. Starfleet
abandoned the TR-116
in favor
of regenerative phasers.
That doesn't mean the killer
couldn't have gotten hold
of the rifle's
replication patterns.
But only Starfleet officers
have access to those files.
Disturbing thought, isn't it?
Starfleet officers do not go
around murdering other officers.
Not usually, anyway.
Hold on a minute.
That's odd.
According to these readings
the bullet only traveled
eight or nine centimeters.
Then the killer must have
fired at point-blank range.
I don't think so.
There are no powder burns
on the body.
What are powder burns?
At close range, chemically
propelled weapons
leave residual
combustion products
on the skin and clothing
of the victims.
How did you know that?
I read 20th century
crime novels...
Raymond Chandler, Mike Hammer...
that sort of thing.
Hmm.
So, if the killer did
fire from close range
why aren't there
any powder burns?
Why aren't there
I don't know.
But we'll find out.
What was the time of death?
0317.
That's only ten minutes
after I left.
Was he alone?
I didn't see anyone
but I wasn't here for very long.
What do we know about Ilario
outside of his service record?
Not a great deal.
He's only been on
the station for ten days.
As far as I could tell
he was intelligent, dedicated,
eager to please.
Everyone liked him.
Not everyone.
I want to know everything
there is to know about him...
who his friends were,
if he made any enemies.
I also want increased
security throughout the station.
Yes, sir.
And, Constable...
You want whoever did this
caught.
I understand, Captain.
Ilario once told me
that he came from a big family...
three brothers and two sisters.
I thought it was two brothers
and three sisters.
I don't think so.
You sure?
Are you?
Don't look at me.
We never discussed his family.
Mostly he talked
about the Academy
and about the two of you.
Us?
He really admired both of you.
We should have let him
come to the holosuite with us.
You're right.
We should have.
I just wish I hadn't left
his quarters so quickly.
Maybe he'd still be alive.
Or you'd be dead
right there with him.
Odo will catch whoever
did this, won't he?
If anyone can.
We really should have
let him come
to the holosuite with us.
Ezri.
Shouldn't you be in bed?
I was about to ask you
the same question.
I just couldn't sleep.
Me, neither.
You mustn't blame
yourself, you know
for Ilario's death.
I don't.
Not really.
Then what is it?
It's just knowing
that he was murdered.
It's difficult to accept.
The whole concept
of someone killing
another person in cold blood...
it's almost
incomprehensible, isn't it?
Not to me.
Meaning what?
Meaning that I know exactly
what it feels like...
to feel the urge,
the need to take a life.
You're talking about Joran.
He killed three people.
He was the host to
the Dax symbiont just like me.
He was nothing like you.
I try not to think about it.
Jadzia felt the same way.
She tried to bury his memories
as deeply as she could...
but they're still there.
The victims...
what they looked like.
They weren't your victims.
I know.
But then something
like this happens and...
Just the thought of someone
like him being here right now.
You really should get some rest.
You're right.
Even if it does mean
lying in my bed
staring at the ceiling
for a few more hours.
Good night, Julian.
Good night.
Save your complaints
for the magistrate.
Is this the one
we've been looking for?
Ilario's killer.
Quite a clever one at that.
Why? Why did you do it?
You tell me, Counselor.
But... you're dead.
Don't tell me.
Tell him.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
There's nothing more annoying
than a corpse
with a mind of its own.
What?!
Dax to Security.
Odo?
Kira?
Anyone there?
Security, please, answer me!
Joran.
You recognize me.
How nice.
What do you want?
Respect, understanding...
Love.
I wish you'd stop being
afraid of me.
It's not like we're strangers.
That worm in your belly
used to be mine
which means I'm part of you.
Joran...
And you're part of me.
I'm nothing like you.
Is that so?
You want to find out
who killed Ilario, don't you?
Then what are you waiting for?
Perform the Rite of Emergence
and just ask for my help
and then we can get to work.
I don't want your help.
Maybe not, but you need it.
You murdered three people.
I don't want anything
to do with you.
Now leave me alone!
How can I?
There's nowhere else
for me to go.
I'm within you, Ezri,
all the time.
Use me.
No!
I can help.
I know how he thinks.
We can catch him, Ezri...
you and me together
and then we'll make him pay.
Sisko to Dax.
Report to Habitat Ring,
Level J-17.
What is it, Ben?
There's been another murder.
Report.
Lieutenant Commander Greta
Vanderweg, Science Officer
human, age 37, 12 years
of service, the last three
here on Deep Space 9.
Cause of death...
tritanium bullet
fired at close range.
No powder burns.
Did Ilario and Vanderweg
know each other?
I'll look into it,
but it's doubtful.
Ilario was only here
for ten days.
Seven of them,
he was on the Defiant.
But why Ilario
and why Vanderweg?
Did someone have
a personal grudge
against either one of them
or is someone just killing
our officers at random?
I still can't believe
anyone in Starfleet
could be doing this.
There are over 900
Starfleet officers
posted on the station.
Odo, we have
to narrow the field of suspects.
Sir.
How well did you do
in forensic psychology
at the Academy?
It wasn't my favorite subject.
We have to find out
why the killer's doing this.
I'll do my best.
I wonder why he chose
a TR-116.
Instead of a phaser?
Yeah. I mean, why use a rifle
if you're going to shoot
somebody from close range?
I don't know.
He or she may have, uh,
originally intended
to kill their victims
from a great distance
so they replicated
a long-range weapon.
Or they had some
special connection
to this particular rifle.
You know, a fetish
or psychological obsession
perhaps.
I suppose so.
Did you ever read
that biography I gave you
on Davy Crockett last month?
No, but I'll get to it.
No, no. There was
this fascinating section
about the mythology that grew up
around Crockett and his rifle.
There was this notion
that a man could have
a special relationship
with a weapon.
Some frontiersmen
even went so far
as to give
their rifles names...
female ones at that...
thus changing the relationship
between owner and object
to something resembling
man and woman.
Hmm. Maybe I'll start calling
my tricorder "Sally."
There's some great tall tales
in that book.
There's one particular story
where Crockett was supposed
to have put up a target
against a tree
and arranged a series
of tin frying pans nearby
in a complicated pattern.
The idea was that he was
going to shoot a bullet
at one of these pans
which would then ricochet
to another and then to another
and then to another
and then to another...
Wait a minute.
That's it.
Displaced targeting...
that's how he did it.
Who?
Well, the killer.
He set up an alternate
bullet trajectory...
one that didn't require
a direct line of sight
between him and the victim.
Julian, you're a genius.
Well, don't thank me.
Thank Davy Crockett.
What do you think?
Nice melon.
But what does it
have to do with us?
I have no idea.
All I know is that
Chief O'Brien wanted me
to bring you here.
He said he has
something to show us.
O'Brien to Science Lab.
Go ahead, Chief.
Are you ready?
For what?
You'll see.
First put on those goggles
that are on the counter
in front of you.
Now, take a step back
away from the melon.
A little further.
I've only done this
a couple of times.
How's this?
Good.
Wow.
Are you all right?
Better than that melon.
It worked.
I was able to fire a bullet
into that melon while standing
outside in the corridor.
You fired through the wall?
I don't see any bullet holes.
I attached a micro-transporter
to this TR-116.
When I fired, the bullet
was beamed into the room
a few centimeters
away from the melon.
Where it continued
its trajectory.
So, if the killer had
a similar transporter device
that would explain
the lack of powder burns
on the victims.
And by using an exographic
targeting sensor
he was able to scan
through the bulkheads.
So, he could have been firing
from anywhere on the station.
Can you trace the bullet's
transporter signatures back
to where the killer was
when he fired?
I'm afraid not.
The signature's too weak.
It's an ingenious weapon.
Whoever he is, he's smart.
Nothing.
No connection.
Who's there?
Who is it?
Quark, is that you?
This isn't funny.
Worf.
It is late.
You should be in your quarters.
Were you following me?
It is dangerous for you
to be wandering
the Promenade alone.
You were worried about me?
There is a killer
on the station.
You have no right
to endanger yourself this way.
You were worried about me.
Thank you, Worf.
That's... sweet.
You are a fellow officer.
I would have the same concern
for Chief O'Brien or Dr. Bashir.
Of course.
I didn't mean
to imply otherwise.
Then we understand each other.
Perfectly.
How is the investigation coming?
Uh... slowly.
If I can assist you
in any way...
I appreciate it,
but you can't, really.
Nobody can.
Actually, that's not true.
There is someone
who could help
but I don't want to ask him.
Why?
It's complicated.
Nevertheless, if he can help...
It wouldn't be very pleasant.
Perhaps not, but I am certain
that you will do whatever is
necessary to complete your task.
And how do you know that?
You are Dax.
It is your way.
I'nora, ja'kala vok...
'za Ezri...
zhian'tara rek...
pora'al Zheem Dax...
Tanas Rhem Joran.
'Za Ezri
Oh, come on, Joran,
don't make me beg.
Joran Tanas Rhem.
Vok Ezri
You won't regret this, Ezri.
I promise.
Joran, the forgotten host
the outcast.
The murderer.
I'm sure you never thought
that little character trait
would prove useful.
Seems so strange
separating you from the others
seeing you standing there.
But I'm not really
standing here, am I?
It's all in your mind.
At least now I know
you're listening to me.
I've been ignored
for far too long.
Curzon and Jadzia didn't
quite know what to do with me.
They buried your memories
as deep within them as possible.
That was a mistake.
I have so much to offer.
We'll see about that.
Now, let's get to work.
We have a killer to catch.
Where shall we begin?
I want to know how he thinks.
Then we'll start
with his choice of weapons.
We already know how
he modified the TR-116.
But you haven't held it
in your hands, have you?
You haven't looked through
its tracking display
picked a target, felt the power
as you lock its sensors
on your unsuspecting prey.
If you want to catch
a killer, Ezri
you have to learn
to think like one.
Handsome weapon.
If you say so.
Come now.
Even you have to admire
the aesthetic qualities
inherent in its design.
It conveys a sense
of danger, of power.
Just looking from the
trigger to the muzzle
conjures up images of death.
Take it down.
I meant "hold it in your hands."
Why?
Because I want you to feel
what the killer felt.
This isn't going to work
if you fight me.
I'm holding the gun.
Stop placating me.
You wanted my help.
Now do as I say.
Put on the targeting display.
Now... hold the weapon as
if you're going to use it.
Feels good, doesn't it?
I've held a rifle before.
You mean in combat.
It's not the same thing.
That kind of killing's
too random, too chaotic.
This is more controlled.
You can savor the moment.
Now, tell me, what do you see?
I'm moving through the different
levels of the Docking Ring.
He didn't kill anyone
in the Docking Ring.
Remember, you're trying
to put yourself in his mind.
Move to the Habitat Ring.
I'm there,
in one of the corridors.
Good.
Our killer is a hunter,
so start hunting.
I see a Bajoran deputy.
You don't want to be
in the corridors.
Look in the quarters.
No one's here.
A male Starfleet officer,
an engineer, about 35.
Good.
We have a victim.
You have him in your sights.
How do you feel?
Truth now.
Powerful.
In control.
Good. That's what
the killer's feeling.
I'm not angry or excited.
You're calm, relaxed...
Detached.
Now you're getting it.
You do your killing
from a distance.
You're cold, methodical.
Maybe you're a scientist
or a doctor.
Maybe...
but why kill like this?
Why not choose a victim
on the Promenade or in Quark's?
If you want to know the answer,
pull the trigger.
Find out.
Don't think about it.
Do it!
No!
Ezri, the gun isn't loaded.
Then why did you tell me
to pull the trigger?
Do you want to know
what the killer
feels or don't you?
I'm sorry, Ezri.
I didn't mean
to push you so far.
I'm not a murderer.
I'm not you.
Maybe not,
but you have my memories.
You remember what it was like...
the excitement, the passion
the looks on their faces
as they realized
we were the last thing
they'd ever see.
That has nothing to do with me!
You're the killer!
Ezri?
I think you need a vacation.
You're talking to yourself.
I'm just thinking out loud.
I don't know what you see
in this Ferengi.
He's repulsive.
Can I get you a drink
or something to eat?
No. We don't have time.
We have work to do.
No, thanks.
I'm not hungry, really.
Well...
when you are,
you know where to come.
How I'd love to slip
a knife between his ribs.
I have a better idea...
let's get back to work.
The sooner we find our killer
the sooner you and I
can part company.
I thought we were
having fun together.
Think again.
I suppose I'll have to
make myself more endearing.
Now, I suggest we visit
the victims' quarters
to see what answers
we can find there.
What are we looking for?
Clues. What else?
But we don't even know
if the killer
ever set foot in here.
Both victims were
in their quarters
when they were killed.
Is that a coincidence
or a connection?
I don't know.
Think about it.
Look around...
and remember, whatever you
see is what the killer saw.
What do we know
about these classmates
of Ilario's?
Odo checked
with Starfleet Command.
The one on the left was killed
in combat five weeks ago.
The one in the middle
is stationed on the USS Truman.
The Truman hasn't come
anywhere near Deep Space 9
in months.
Hmm... pity.
Keep looking.
Greta was quite a pack rat,
wasn't she?
She was here a long time.
This was home.
A monument to bad taste.
Just an observation.
Vanderweg's husband
is a micropaleontologist
on Mora V.
She was married.
Ilario was single.
She was on Deep Space 9
for three years.
He just got here.
She was a mature woman.
He was practically a kid.
Besides the uniform
they have
absolutely nothing in common...
which means they could've
just been chosen at random...
and if that's the case,
then we're wasting our time.
You're thinking of giving up,
aren't you?
I didn't say that.
You don't have to.
You have failure
written all over you.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
It's not the lack of
clues that's keeping you
from finding the killer...
it's you.
Me?
You're holding back, Ezri.
You refuse to see with his eyes
feel with his hands,
think with his mind.
You want to turn me
into a killer
make me like you.
You are me.
You want me to kill someone?
What do you say I start
with you?
That's the spirit.
Hold it!
Stop him!
They found him.
Stop that man!
A weapon! Over there!
Yes, yes, do it.
Do it!
That's enough!
You mind explaining this?
I'm told that if Odo
hadn't stopped you
you'd have stabbed
Ensign Bertram.
I was trying to stop him
from getting away.
All right. He hit me,
I reacted...
I guess I overreacted.
I'd say so.
He could be a little
more appreciative
don't you think?
I'm sorry things got out of hand
but Bertram killed two people.
Bertram didn't kill anyone.
Then why was
a security team chasing him?
Because a month ago
he accessed the replicator
patterns on TR-116
without authorization.
Sounds guilty to me.
Why would he replicate a rifle
unless he was going to use it?
Because he collects weapons...
Federation, Klingon, Cardassian.
What a coincidence.
That doesn't
rule him out as a suspect.
True, but the fact
that he was on Bajor
when the first murder occurred
does.
You've been under
a lot of stress lately, so...
Ben, please don't give up on me.
I can find this murderer.
I know I can.
I just need more time.
I don't know what you
and Jadzia and Curzon
all see in that man.
He's so insufferable,
so Starfleet.
I'm surprised the killer
hasn't targeted him.
I'm joking, of course
but he did come perilously close
to derailing our investigation.
And you have to take
some of the blame for that.
What did I do?
It's what you didn't do, really.
You should have
told him about me.
You're kidding.
One word about you
and he'd have pulled
me off the case.
Well, then, I guess I'll have
to remain your little secret
and be glad that you're
still in his good graces.
Not that it matters, really.
We would have continued on
without Sisko's blessing.
Right?
What are you doing?
What does it look like?
I'nora, ja'kala vok...
Do you really think
you can get rid
of me this easily?
Zheem Dax nah
sass-eye-ahn...
Don't you realize
we've made Dax whole again?
D'za-oo bah-zheest...
Don't back away now.
Joran rhee jehr hey-dah...
Joran rhee jehr hey-dah.
You won't catch
the killer without me.
Odo to Lieutenant Dax.
Report to the Habitat Ring,
on H-43.
I'm on my way.
Petty officer Zim Brott; Bolian.
Five years of service
on Deep Space 9.
I knew him.
Or, at least, Jadzia did.
He has a wife and
co-husband on Bolarus.
Well, so much for the theory
that our killer
only targets humans.
Captain...
The bullet pierced his heart?
At close range.
Why am I not surprised?
What if we don't catch him?
Will he keep shooting
Starfleet officers
till there are none
left on the station?
How could anyone be so happy
with such unattractive
children?
What did you say?
This photo.
That's it.
It's the pictures.
He's laughing.
She's laughing.
That's what the victims
have in common...
pictures of laughing faces.
A killer who hates laughter
who hates emotion.
A Vulcan.
All Vulcans distrust emotions
but they don't go around
killing people for smiling.
This one does.
Something happened to him.
Something so
emotionally painful
it's making him lose control.
When he looks through
the targeting sensor
and sees those pictures,
the laughter seems to mock him.
You're thinking like he thinks.
Good, Ezri.
Computer, how many
Vulcan Starfleet officers
are on the station?
There are 48 Vulcans
serving on Deep Space 9.
Now all we have to do
is eliminate 47 of them.
I should tell Odo.
Not until we have proof.
Then let's get some.
We still have 28 suspects...
Vulcans who have suffered
a personal loss of some kind.
We've narrowed the field.
Not by enough.
There's one thing
I don't understand...
if he hates laughter
then why doesn't he
seek out his victims
in Quark's or the holosuite?
Maybe it's not
just the laughter.
You're right.
Maybe it has something to do
with... the way the photograph
freezes the emotion
making it seem like the laughter
is going to last forever.
Level 12, Central Core.
So, what do we do now?
We go back over
our list of suspects
see if we can't narrow it down.
Then, proof or no proof,
we give the list to Odo.
Habitat Ring, Level K-55.
What are you doing?
Are you addressing me?
Sorry.
Never mind.
It's him, Ezri.
I know it is.
We've found our killer.
I'm telling you
he's the one
we're looking for.
Look in his eyes.
By the way, I'm Counselor Dax.
I know.
What are you doing?
He's getting away.
We need proof...
something I can take to Odo.
And while you're
looking for that proof
what do you think
the Vulcan will be doing?
Let me tell you.
He's going to pick
another victim.
Science Officer Chu'lak, age 97
assigned to Deep Space 9
three months ago.
Before that, he served
aboard the USS Grissom.
Why was he transferred?
The Grissom was destroyed
by the Jem'Hadar
in the battle of Ricktor Prime.
He was one of only
six crewmen to survive.
Six survivors
out of a crew of 1,250.
He served on that
ship for ten years.
Those people who were killed
were his colleagues...
his friends.
That's a painful loss,
even for a Vulcan.
That doesn't
make him a killer.
But your instincts
tell you that he is.
Listen to your instincts.
Listen to me.
It's him.
Computer, locate
Science Officer Chu'lak.
Lieutenant Chu'lak
is in his quarters.
Seeking out his next victim.
Computer, where are
Chu'lak's quarters?
Habitat Ring, Level D-12.
My thought, exactly.
What do you see?
He's studying something
on his computer console.
Studying what?
What is it?
Me.
My service record.
He knows we suspect him.
He's going into the next room.
What's he doing?
He's coming back.
He's carrying something.
It's a rifle, isn't it?
Isn't it?
Yes.
Shoot him.
Don't think about it.
Just do it.
Kill him.
Oh.
Congratulations.
I'm proud of you.
Go ahead.
Finish what you started.
Tell me, why did you do it?
Because logic demanded it.
What are you waiting for?
He deserves to die.
You know that.
Follow your instincts.
Dax to Infirmary.
I need
an emergency medical team
Habitat Ring, D-12.
On our way.
Try not to look
so disappointed.
J'zui vok Ezri
shay-hal-bah-sha.
I'nora, ja'kala vok...
I can't tell you
how much I've enjoyed
our time together.
Zheem Dax...
nah sass-eye-ahn...
D'za-oo bah-zheest...
Joran rhee jehr hey-dah...
You won't be able to forget me
or bury me as deeply
as Curzon and Jadzia did.
I know.
I'm part of you now.
As much as Audrid,
Torias... any of them.
I'll have to be careful.
Tu Dax
noh zhian 'vok...
j'zui...
Joran Rhem Tanas...
Ezri.