How long was I asleep?
Almost two hours.
You dropped out of warp.
Must be close to home.
We entered the Bajoran system
a few minutes ago.
What's that?
The shopkeeper I bought it from
called it a "knickknack."
I didn't know
you collected knickknacks.
It's a present for Kira.
Oh...
You, you don't think
she'll like it?
Oh, I'm sure she'll like it.
It's just that I didn't get
anything for Keiko.
Ah.
Well, the conference kept
you pretty busy.
Well, you found time
to get something.
Not chocolates as well.
Hmm. Rigelian chocolates...
her favorite.
I'll buy them from you.
I beg your pardon?
Come on, Odo.
You don't have to give her
two presents.
You've only been gone a day.
I'm sorry, Miles,
but the answer is no.
There's something behind us.
It's gaining on us fast.
You think it's friendly?
I hope so.
It's certainly taken
an interest in us.
Uh-oh.
It's gone.
- What?
- According to the sensors
there's nothing out there.
Well, where'd it go?
It's a changeling.
Stay where you are,
or I'll fire.
You.
You are a Metamorph.
I'm a changeling, yes.
Tell the mono-form
to put down its weapon.
Why did you board our ship?
Because I sensed you were here.
I had to see if it were true...
if I'd finally found
another Metamorph.
You've never met
another shape-shifter?
I've been trying to find others
of my kind for a long time.
I told you to stay
where you are.
How do we know
he's not a Founder?
He's not.
He's one of the hundred.
The hundred?
Over the centuries,
our people sent out
100 infant changelings
into the galaxy.
We were to learn
about other species
and eventually return home
to share what we'd experienced.
That would explain
why I was alone on Varala.
I didn't even know
what I was at first
or that I could assume
other forms.
I was the same way.
I hate to interrupt,
but shouldn't we get him
into a containment field
until we're sure
he's telling the truth?
I will allow myself
to be taken prisoner
to show my good faith
but only if you vouch
for my safety.
I do not trust...
humanoids.
So, where is he now?
In a holding cell.
Captain, he's not
a threat to us.
He's just a changeling
who's traveled a long way
to find out
where he came from.
You believe his story?
Yes, sir, I do.
How can we be sure
he's not a Founder?
If he were a Founder,
he'd be infected
with the same disease that's
afflicting the entire Link.
I asked Dr. Bashir to scan him.
His morphogenic matrix
is as stable as mine.
Sir, with your permission,
I'd like to release him.
Well, Constable,
I'm sure you can appreciate
why I'd have reservations
about that.
We're still at war
with your people.
The Founders have
deceived us before.
I realize that, sir,
but he is not a Founder.
He's one of the hundred.
I'm sure of it.
Sir... I'm asking you
to trust me on this.
All right, Constable.
I'll release him
into your custody.
Thank you, sir.
When I found out our people were
the leaders of the Dominion
I realized I had
no place with them.
This war they're fighting
is wrong.
I can understand
their distrust of humanoids
but why try to conquer them?
Better to avoid them altogether.
You don't much care
for humanoids.
I know from experience
they don't much care
for changelings.
I think you'll find
the people here are different.
Oh?
They accepted me.
Have they?
Is that why you stayed?
I told you I want no part
of the Founders.
But what about the hundred
that were sent out?
Haven't you tried
to find any of them?
No.
It's a huge galaxy.
They could be anywhere.
Hmm. I found you.
I have a life here.
I have... friends.
Constable.
When did you first
assume humanoid form?
A little over 30 years ago.
So that's it.
It's all still so new to you.
I spent the first part
of my life
living among humanoids as well.
How long ago was that?
Over 200 years.
Oh...
I must have been sent out
earlier than you.
Or it could be
that I was adrift
for a long time
before I was found.
Either way, it would explain
why you've chosen to stay here.
I, too, was fascinated
by humanoid life
in the beginning.
But, uh, you lost interest.
I found it limiting.
The Varalans never accepted
me as one of them
and I was never really
able to fully mimic
their appearance.
Faces aren't easy.
No, and humanoids are not
very tolerant of difference.
Some of them are.
There are dozens
of species on this station
and they tolerate each other's
differences very well.
Hmm.
He has bumps on his forehead.
She has a wrinkled nose,
but basically they're alike.
They are bipeds that eat,
sleep, breathe.
You and I are nothing like them.
We're changelings.
We can be like them
when we choose.
I choose to be like them
as little as possible.
That's where we differ.
Let me show you where
you'll be staying.
You haven't told me your name.
The Varalans called me Laas.
In their language it
means "changeable."
Not very imaginative, is it?
At least it's appropriate.
Mine means "unknown sample."
The scientist who found
me didn't know what I was.
These are my quarters.
I'll be staying...
somewhere else.
Feel free to shape-shift
as you please.
Some of these forms
are quite interesting.
This hasn't been used
in some time.
I've... been busy.
Who is this?
Her name is Kira.
Ah, I had a mate once.
Oh?
On Varala.
Not long after I first
assumed humanoid form.
And... what happened?
We couldn't have children.
Uh, that was important to her.
Is it something that matters
to this Kira?
We've never discussed it.
Neither did we... at first.
Do our people reproduce?
It's more complicated than that.
In our natural state
we don't exist
as separate entities.
I don't understand.
Our people spend most
of their time in the Link.
The Link?
It involves a melding into one...
a merging of thought
and form, idea...
and sensation.
You're speaking in riddles.
It's difficult to explain.
Then don't.
Show me.
Of course.
Take it.
For the first time in my life,
I understand...
how I was meant to exist.
You've given up a great deal
to remain here.
Yes.
Yes, I have.
But I won't have anything to do
with the Founders and their war.
Odo...
we linked.
I know the truth.
You stayed here because of Kira.
If it weren't for her
you would be with our people,
war or no war.
You would be...
a Founder.
Hi.
Hello, Nerys.
I can't believe it.
Another changeling.
What's he like?
He's...
complicated.
Like you.
You all right?
I'm fine.
You seem far away.
We linked.
I see.
There's nothing to worry about.
He's not a Founder.
He's not trying to lure me
to the Dominion.
The Link is part of what we are.
It comes as naturally to us
as talking does to humanoids.
It's a little more personal
than-than talking, isn't it?
I suppose.
So...
do I get to meet him?
If you like.
I would.
Then I'll arrange it.
Here they are.
This is Laas.
- Nerys.
- Julian.
- Ezri.
- Miles.
We've met.
Look, I'm sorry.
We didn't know
who you were at first.
You gave us quite a scare
when you rammed the runabout.
I've always wondered
how it would feel
to be able to fly
through space like that.
It's a shame you're incapable
of ever experiencing it.
Guess so.
Tell us about Varala.
No Federation ship's
ever been there.
It's just the same
as any other planet...
overrun with humanoids
cities and farms everywhere
other life-forms
displaced from their habitats.
Once I migrated
to the southern continent
with a herd of volg.
When we returned
to our breeding grounds
the following summer,
they had been fenced off.
The herd died out
within two generations.
It's always that way
where humanoids thrive.
They disrupt
the natural balance.
Who ordered the vilm-steak?
Uh, um,
you better keep that warm.
Whatever you say.
The truth is I prefer
the so-called
primitive life-forms.
They exist
as they were meant to...
by following...
their instincts.
No words get in the way,
no lies, no deceptions.
We're not the ones
who can disguise ourselves
as anything we want.
Meaning?
Meaning shape-shifters
are not to be trusted.
I trust Odo.
Of course, you trust Odo.
Look at him.
You've convinced him
that he is as limited
as you are.
Laas...
You've seen through
our evil plan.
Oop. Foiled again.
It's not funny.
No.
I'm very worried for him.
Odo can take care of himself.
Thank you, Colonel.
Well...
this has been...
interesting.
If you'll excuse us, Colonel,
Counselor, Doctor, Chief?
Laas?
Nice to see you again.
This way.
Was it really necessary
to insult my friends?
I was merely speaking my mind.
Well, you could call it that.
Humanoids are such
tragic creatures.
They've lost the ability
to take joy in simply existing
and yet they haven't
evolved to the next level
where consciousness exists
independent of form.
You're certainly not afraid
to make grand generalizations.
Well, I've been many
things in my time, Odo.
I speak from experience.
Enough talk.
Link with me.
Here?
Why not?
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Are you embarrassed?
No.
You don't want to do anything
to remind them
that you're not
truly a humanoid.
I don't go out of my way
to point it out, no.
Why not?
Are you afraid
they will reject you?
I don't like to confront
people with something
that might make
them uncomfortable.
So, you deny your true nature
in order to fit in?
You're reading too much into it.
Before I came here
when was the last time
you assumed another form?
You can't even remember.
You've been pretending
to be a humanoid for so long
it doesn't even occur to you
that you can be anything else.
That's not true.
I've just been involved with...
other things lately.
Like what, courting Kira?
She can't even link with you.
Leave her out of this.
It won't last.
The fact
that your relationship failed
doesn't mean that mine will.
True.
And, if you're very lucky
you can watch her
grow old and die.
I think you should stay
out of my affairs.
I don't want to see you
make the same mistakes I made.
You're wasting your time
trying to be a humanoid.
You're limiting yourself.
Let's leave here, Odo.
Let's find the others.
100 were sent away
and they're out there...
somewhere.
If we can find even a few of
them, we can form a new Link.
Think of it, Odo.
We can exist
the way we were meant to.
As changelings.
I can't believe
he actually thought
you'd just drop everything
and leave with him.
He just can't understand
why I want to stay here.
How did he take it
when you said no?
You did say no, didn't you?
I told him I'd think about it.
I didn't want to dismiss
it out of hand.
He would have taken offense.
Why do you look at me like that?
It just... bothers me
that he thinks
that you're not happy here.
Makes me think he knows
something that I don't.
What makes you say that?
He linked with you.
Ah.
Something about that
gave him the impression that...
you might want to leave here.
It's just wishful
thinking on his part.
The thought of the two
of us going off together
looking for the others
exploring the galaxy
as changelings...
it's very alluring.
To him.
Sounds like it's alluring
to you, too.
I'm... happy...
here.
I'm sorry
I can't link with you.
It doesn't matter, Nerys.
I love you.
Computer, activate
fire suppression sys...
Laas?
I need to talk to you.
You didn't realize it was me.
Did you even know we
could exist as fire?
I didn't think so.
No matter.
Once we're away from here
I'll teach you to become things
you've never even dreamed of.
I'm not leaving.
I'm staying here.
Why?
So you can keep on pretending
to be one of them?
I'm sorry
if you're disappointed.
I'll survive.
And when I find
some of the others...
I'll send for you.
You'll change your mind.
You'll join us.
It could take a long time for
you to find another changeling.
Is that supposed
to discourage me?
All I'm saying is you don't have
to leave right away.
I wouldn't mind the company
of another changeling.
I'm sure you
wouldn't mind either.
All right, Odo.
I won't abandon you
to these mono-forms.
As a favor to you...
I'll stay a while.
Well, you might as well.
If you can't get along with me
what makes you think you can get
along with any other changeling?
Just remember, I have
no interest in mono-forms
even if they are your...
friends.
After what happened at Quark's,
I don't think
you have to worry about
an overcrowded social schedule.
Good.
Children, children.
What?
Great. The environmental
system's out again.
There goes our holosuite
reservation.
I better go see
what the problem is.
Don't bother, Chief.
There's nothing wrong with
the environmental system.
Then where's all
this fog coming from?
It's not fog.
It's Laas.
Laas?
What's he doing?
Being fog.
What's it look like?
Can't he be fog somewhere else?
Or at night
when nobody's around?
He's not hurting anyone.
Still...
it's kind of creepy.
Careful, Miles.
He might hear you.
Good.
Laas?
Laas.
Well... congratulations.
You've managed to disrupt
the entire Promenade.
I was just relaxing.
If you want to relax,
do it in private.
Did I embarrass you?
Ka'vek!
What is this Founder doing here?
He's not a Founder.
Now, move along.
Don't change form
in my presence again.
I will change form
where I please.
Look at him.
Look at the hate in his eyes.
Laas.
Your hands are stained with
the blood of Klingon warriors.
But then the stench
would still be on them.
P'tak!
Mine's bigger.
Ke'chaw!
No.
No!
Dr. Bashir wasn't able
to save the Klingon's life.
General Martok
has asked that Laas be detained
until the magistrate
can determine jurisdiction.
Jurisdiction?
The Klingons
want to extradite him.
That's ridiculous.
He killed that Klingon
in self-defense.
That is in dispute.
He was about to draw
his disrupter.
According to the other Klingon,
he was reaching for his dagger.
Are you saying that's not true?
It all happened too fast, but
their intentions were obvious.
One of them put a knife
in his chest.
The Klingons are arguing
that since Laas knew
he couldn't be harmed by a knife
that he wasn't justified
in responding with deadly force.
Since when do the Klingons
resort to legal quibbling?
They get involved in fights
all the time.
They never file charges.
It isn't honorable.
In this case, the Klingons
are exercising their rights
under the law.
Sir, they are only doing this
because they distrust
changelings.
He should not have
provoked them.
Provoked them?
They attacked Laas.
They claim he surrounded them
menacingly.
They felt menaced by fog.
They weren't the only ones.
There are 12 other people
who filed complaints.
Is it a crime to shape-shift
on the Promenade?
It's not a crime, but it's
obviously not a good idea.
You're going to allow
the Klingons to extradite him
knowing they won't give him
a fair trial.
That's not my decision.
It's up to the magistrate.
But you'd just as soon
be rid of him.
You never wanted him on the
station in the first place.
I practically had to beg you
to let him
out of that holding cell.
That's quite enough, Constable.
Now, Martok has expressed
some concerns
about our security arrangements.
Meaning?
He's not sure it's appropriate
that you should be
in charge of the prisoner.
May I ask why?
Because you were a witness
to the alleged crime.
Well, that's a relief.
For a moment, I thought you were
going to say it's because...
I'm a changeling.
Odo.
I heard about your friend.
Rumor has it the Klingons
want to put him on trial.
They're the ones who
should be put on trial.
If they'd attacked anyone
other than a changeling
they would be.
You're probably right.
That fog episode certainly
didn't help matters.
Laas was only doing
what comes naturally to us.
You never pulled
a stunt like that.
You're smart enough to know
that people don't want
to be reminded
that you're different.
Who wants to see
somebody turn into goo?
I hope you don't do that
around Kira.
Why shouldn't I?
Well, if she's anything like me,
she'd rather you didn't.
Don't you get it, Odo?
We humanoids are a product
of millions of years
of evolution.
Our ancestors learned
the hard way
that what you don't know
might kill you.
They wouldn't have survived
if they hadn't have jumped back
when they encountered
a snake coiled in the muck.
And, now,
millions of years later
that instinct is still there.
It's genetic.
Our tolerance to other
life-forms doesn't extend
beyond the two-arm,
two-leg variety.
I hate to break this to you...
but when you're
in your natural state...
you're more than
our poor old genes can handle.
So what are you saying, Quark?
That the Klingons
couldn't help what they did
because of their genes?
I'm not trying to excuse
what they did.
I'm only telling you
why it happened.
Watch your step, Odo.
We're at war with your people.
This is no time
for a changeling pride
demonstration on the Promenade.
Constable.
I'd like to have
a few minutes alone
with the prisoner.
Sorry, sir.
I have my orders.
I don't know what to say.
You could say you were wrong.
You could say the people here
are no different
than any other humanoids.
Hopefully, this will all
get straightened out
at your hearing.
I am sure it will be
fair and impartial.
Just tell them
exactly what happened.
My word against a humanoid's.
Whom do you think
this magistrate
is going to believe?
I shouldn't have
convinced you to stay.
If I had just... let you go
none of this
would have happened.
My only consolation
is that this may
finally make you understand
that you don't belong here.
You saw the hatred
in that Klingon's eyes.
Perhaps now you'll recognize it
when you see it
hiding in the faces
of your so-called friends.
They tolerate you, Odo...
because you emulate them.
What higher flattery is there?
"I, who can be anything,
choose to be like you."
But even when you make yourself
in their image
they know you are not truly
one of them.
They know that what you appear
to be does not reflect
what you really are.
It's only a mask.
What lies underneath
is alien to them
and so they fear it.
And that fear can turn to hate
in the blink of an eye.
They're going to extradite him.
You don't know that.
Yes, I do, and no one is going
to do anything to stop it.
There's not much anyone can do.
If he weren't a changeling
the Captain would find
a way to intervene.
Oh, no, that's unfair.
Is it?
You're starting
to sound like Laas.
Well, maybe that's
because I'm starting
to see things more clearly now.
What is that supposed to mean?
Look at me, Nerys.
What do you see?
I see you.
No. No, this is just
a form I borrowed.
I could just as easily be
someone or something else.
I know that
but this...
is what you have
always chosen to be.
A man...
a good and honest man...
a man I fell in love with.
Are you trying to tell me
that he never really existed?
I don't know.
I care for you
more than anyone
I've ever known.
These last few months have
been the happiest of my life.
But even so...
part of me wishes that Laas
and I were out there right now
searching for the others
existing as changelings.
Because that's what I am.
Not a humanoid.
I'm a changeling.
Well, then maybe you're right.
Maybe you do belong out there.
Can I help you, Colonel?
Uh... I need to talk
to the prisoner.
Alone.
Aye, sir.
Go to the third planet
in the Koralis system.
You'll find an orbital tether
running down to
an abandoned mining complex.
I'll tell Odo to meet you there.
Is this some kind of a trick?
Do you want to get out of here
or not?
That vent will lead you through
some conduits to an airlock.
Why?
I love him.
Escaped?
How did he get through
the containment field?
I can't explain it.
All I can tell you
is what I saw.
He turned into some kind
of plasma energy
and forced his way through.
Before I could stop him,
he had disappeared
into the air vent.
According to the operations log
one of the airlocks was
activated shortly after that.
If he left the station
why didn't our sensors
detect him?
A Corvallen freighter was
leaving about the same time.
He must have shadowed it
to keep from being spotted.
He could be anywhere by now.
General Martok is not going
to be happy about this.
By fleeing, the changeling
has demonstrated his guilt.
Either that, or his lack of
faith in our justice system.
He must be apprehended
and brought to trial.
Mr. Worf,
have all available runabouts
begin a sector-wide search.
Aye, sir.
Good luck.
Constable, I know
it's a long shot
but I'm sure you can agree
we should do everything we can
to find him.
Of course.
Dismissed.
Level 9.
You didn't hide it very well...
that you're glad he escaped.
I should have known
he'd be able to escape.
What's a force field
to a changeling
with his abilities?
You said you wished you
were out there with him.
Well, it's not too late.
I don't understand.
He's waiting for you at an
abandoned mine on Koralis III.
You... helped him escape?
I don't want you
to stay here under some...
sense of obligation.
Good luck.
I hope you find
what you're looking for.
Laas?
I knew you would come.
This is a new beginning
for us, Odo
a new beginning for our people.
You and I are about to embark
on the adventure of our lives.
What's wrong?
I'm not going with you.
Why are you here?
I've come to say good-bye.
Don't be a fool.
What are you holding on to?
Kira?
Even she knows that this
is what's best for you.
Why else would she have
helped me to escape?
You really don't know, do you?
You've no idea what it means
to love someone enough
to let them go.
She let you go
so that you could find out
where you belong.
I know where I belong.
Laas...
humanoids are not
the petty, limited creatures
you perceive them to be.
What Nerys did should
prove that, even to you.
Love conquers all.
Is that it?
I'm sorry you can't understand.
You've done many things
been many things...
but you've never known love.
Compared to the Link
it is a pale shadow
a feeble attempt to compensate
for the isolation
that mono-forms feel
because they are trapped
within themselves.
Perhaps the fact
that it's not easy
is what makes it worthwhile.
Odo...
the Founders are dying.
This could be your last chance
to exist the way
you were meant to.
Don't throw it away.
You'd better go.
They're looking for you.
Good luck.
And to you, Odo.
You'll need it more than I.
Watch over him.
Help him find his way.
Yes.
I didn't think
I'd see you again.
I couldn't go.
If I ever made you feel that you
couldn't be yourself with me...
I'm sorry.
I want to know you...
the way you really are.