VIC:
Sure, I remember
The Alamo.
See? I told you he would.
Laurence Harvey, Richard Widmark
and John Wayne
as Davy Crockett.
Great battle scenes,
nice sets, but way too long.
We're not talking
about a movie.
No, we're, we're talking
about our holosuite program.
Oh, that Alamo.
What about it?
Well, we've got
Holosuite 4 booked for an hour
and were wondering
whether you'd like to join us?
Look, fellas, I'm touched by
the offer, but I don't know.
Well, we can transfer
your matrix to
the Alamo program.
You've got to leave
Vegas sometimes, right?
Oh, true, but I'm afraid
I have to say no.
Why?
I don't look good in buckskin.
( laughs )
VIC:
Tell you what I'll do, though.
How about a little tune
to get you
into a Texas state of mind?
Fellas... "Alamo."
( moderate jazz bass intro )
♪ Standing around by the Alamo ♪
♪ Walkin' around
in San Antonio ♪
♪ Looking around
for a new kind of love ♪
♪ Baby, I'm lonesome tonight ♪
( crowd complaining )
♪ History abounds
by this famous fort ♪
♪ Davy Crockett really came... ♪
( slow, sexy saxophone playing)
( men hooting )
( whistling )
Hey, come on, step down here!
( whistles and hoots continue)
MAN:
Oh, honey!
MAN 2:
Show me, show me!
Way to go, baby!
Off the stage!
Get down!
What the hell... ?
What is all this?!
Don't ask me!
Maybe there's a pointer fault
in the holosuite's
parameter file.
MAN:
Well, look
who's here.
The pretty boy singer himself.
Frankie Eyes.
What are you doing in Vegas?
Whatever happened to
"Hello, Frankie.
Long time no see.
"Make yourself at home.
Can I get
you anything?"
Do you believe
this guy?
No manners.
You born in a barn
or something?
This gentleman
a friend of yours?
We know each other.
We're a long way from South
Philly, ain't we, Vic?
So, are you here on business
or pleasure?
Let's just say I'm here to stay
while you, Vicky-boy,
are about to take a powder.
I'm not going anywhere.
I got news
for you, pal
I just bought
this hotel.
You're history.
You can't fire me.
I have a contract.
And you can paper your walls
with it.
You're finished
in this town, Vic.
You're blackballing me?
As of this moment
you couldn't get a job
as a singing busboy.
Now, are you going
to walk out of here
or do you have
to be carried out?
Makes no difference to me.
Let me handle this.
Computer, delete characters
Frankie Eyes
and, uh-- I'm sorry
I didn't catch
your name.
Cicci.
Cicci!
Cicci from the
holosuite's program.
What's a holosuites?
Beats me.
They're still
here, Chief.
Computer, freeze program.
There must be a little
problem in the character
deletion
algorithm...
I'll show you the door.
Make that a big problem.
So, what's it going
to be, pally?
I guess I start packing.
Smart boy.
All right, Cicci, come on.
Let's check out my casino.
So, what do we do now?
Nothing we can do.
Frankie's a made
man, capisce?
No, I'm not talking
about Frankie.
I'm talking about fixing
the entire program.
Well, we could shut it down
manually and reset it
but that would wipe
Vic's memory.
He'd forget everything
that's happened
since we activated him.
Oh, hold on, pally.
Nobody's wiping my memory.
Of course not.
But there must be
some other way.
I wish I knew
what it was.
I better
talk to Felix.
After all, he was the one
who designed this program.
You do that.
In the meantime
you stay out of the way
of Frankie Eyes.
You'll get no argument from me.
I'll tell you one thing.
If this Frankie Eyes
hurts Vic in any way
he's going to have
to answer to me.
I do not understand
how you could feel
such loyalty for a hologram.
He's not just a hologram.
He's my friend.
Don't you like Vic?
As a singer, I find him...
entertaining.
But beyond that, I neither
like him nor dislike him.
He is a hologram
and therefore,
he does not exist.
He does for me.
I just talked to Felix.
I know what's been affecting
Vic's program.
It's a jack-in-the-box.
A what?
A jack-in-the-box.
It's a children's toy on Earth.
You wind it up and a figure
pops out and goes "boo."
Except this kind
of jack-in-the-box is different.
It doesn't
go "boo."
No.
This surprise is buried deep
in the holosuite program.
It's meant to shake things up
you know--
make things interesting.
I wasn't bored, were you?
Not at all.
I liked Vic's the way it was.
Well, according to Felix,
if we get rid of Frankie Eyes
everything resets
back to the way it was.
Well, that's good to know.
So, how do we get rid
of Frankie Eyes?
BASHIR:
Now, that's up to us.
But Felix did warn me
the program is period specific.
In other words,
if we shoot him
we have to use a .45 automatic
and not a phaser.
We can't shoot Frankie.
It's too dangerous.
The mob could retaliate
against Vic.
If anything happens
to Vic, his matrix
will be eliminated from
the program, permanently.
The news just keeps getting
better, doesn't it?
What news?
Oh, nothing, sir.
We're, uh, talking
about a holosuite program.
BASHIR:
Vic Fontaine's hotel
has just been bought by...
gangsters.
I see.
When do you plan
on going back to work?
Right away, sir.
Whatever you
decide to do, Chief
count me in.
I owe Vic.
I thought losing my leg
was the end
of my Starfleet career.
He taught me
otherwise.
KIRA:
He changed
my life, too...
and Odo's.
Now...
all we need's a plan.
Mmm.
Your daddy would be proud.
My daddy taught me
everything I know.
How nice.
So, how was your day?
It's getting better.
Did something happen?
It's Vic.
Vic?
Vic Fontaine.
A gangster
named Frankie Eyes
took over his lounge.
The whole place has changed
and no one's sure
how to change it back.
What?
Nothing.
I guess this sounds
pretty silly to you.
A little.
You have to understand
Vic isn't just another
holosuite program.
He's more like a friend.
Kasidy, can we talk
about something else?
Sure.
How come you've
never been to Vic's?
Does it matter?
You like going there,
and I don't.
Let's leave it at that.
I was only asking.
And I gave you my answer.
There are times when I
just can't figure you out.
Well... maybe that's part
of the attraction.
Believe that if you want to.
VIC:
Who is it?
It's Miles and Julian.
Just a minute.
( clunking )
You wouldn't
happen to have
an ice pack on you,
would y...?
Hey, pally.
Whose side are you on?
I'm sorry, but you've got
three bruised ribs here
and your left wrist
is sprained.
But the good news is
your skull
is still in one piece.
Thanks.
I feel better already.
That jack-in-the-box.
I can't believe Felix
would do that to me.
Oh, don't take it
personally, Vic.
He was just trying
to do me a favor
by not letting things
get too boring.
I thought that
was my job.
Oh, and you're
great at it.
You know,
we love you.
So, you gonna tell us
what happened?
I slipped in the bathtub.
Oh, yeah... and you
knocked over this furniture
looking for a bandage, right?
Something like that.
Frankie sent Tony Cicci
to pay me a little visit.
He wanted to remind me not
to take too long packing.
What is it with you and Frankie?
It goes back to the
old neighborhood
when we were kids.
I used to beat him
at stickball.
And?
And...
Nothing. We've been
rivals ever since.
That Felix, huh?
When he designs a holosuite
program, he doesn't fool around.
Huh. Tell me about it.
Now, you should
get some rest.
Maybe take a
little vacation.
A vacation?
Did you guys take
a vacation
when the Dominion
took over DS9?
It's not the same thing.
It is to me.
This is my life, remember?
I don't run at the
first sign of trouble.
We're not asking you
to run anywhere.
We just want you
to stay out of sight
while we come up
with a plan.
What plan?
How to get rid of Frankie Eyes.
Odo and Kira are in
the lounge right now.
Doing what?
Checking up on Frankie.
We need to find his weak spot.
I hope you know what
you're getting me into.
If you guys screw up
I'm the one who winds up
buried in the desert.
( sultry jazz playing )
MAN:
Here we go, here we go.
Let me guess.
You'll look around here
while I check out the casino?
Oh... uh, if you prefer,
I'll go, uh...
Enjoy yourself.
Just remember--
we have a job to do.
Of course.
( men laughing )
MAN:
Then I drive him
out to the woods.
Badda-bing,
badda-bang!
Three shots in the
back of the head.
That's the end
of Little Paulie.
So, what do you
think Frankie says
when I report back in?
"Little Paulie?!
No! I told you to pop
Big Paulie!"
( all laughing )
That's the problem
with our business--
too many guys
named Paulie!
KIRA:
Hit me.
I'm done.
Not so fast.
What kind of card is that
to give such
a pretty lady?
Hit her again.
Isn't that against the rules?
Don't worry about it.
Double your bet.
Twenty-six.
What's wrong
with you?
Again.
You're starting to
aggravate me, pal.
Twenty-one.
Finally.
Pay the lady.
Yes, sir.
If I were you, I'd, uh,
quit while I was ahead.
Hmm.
The name's Frank Chalmers
but everyone calls me
Frankie Eyes.
Why is that?
'Cause I don't
miss a trick.
You're very sure
of yourself.
Well, doubt
is for losers.
And quite
a philosopher.
Well, I'm thinking
of writing a book.
What's the title?
Well, maybe you could
help me think one up.
My talents lie
in other directions.
Good title.
Mind if I use it?
I'd say you already
paid for it.
So what do you say we, uh,
hit the roulette table
and see if I can't
buy Chapter One?
Hey, Max...
Max, come here.
I want you
to see this.
Ah! Ah!
I don't believe it.
He did it again.
Buddy, I've been hanging out
in bars for 20 years.
I ain't never seen
a stunt like that.
There's nothing
to it, really.
Did you hear that?
Guy's the eighth
wonder of the world
and he says there's
nothing to it.
So, where you
from again?
Bajor.
That's in Jersey, right?
Right.
Max, Max...
another round
for my friend here.
Turns out Frankie Eyes
was sent to Vegas
by a man named
Carl Zeemo.
Huh. Looks like Frankie's
moving up in the world.
You know
Mr. Zeemo?
Been around forever.
Likes to pretend
he's a sweet old man
but he's meaner
than a junkyard dog.
This is all starting
to make sense.
I knew Frankie didn't have
the money to buy a hotel.
But Zeemo does.
More than
enough.
This is going to be
a pretty sweet deal for him.
The casino's bringing in
about a million bucks a month--
cash--
and out of that,
Zeemo expects to be sent
a couple hundred grand.
That would be the "skim."
Right off the top.
Tax free.
Frankie's got nothing
to worry about.
All he's got to do
is send Mr. Zeemo his cut.
KIRA:
According
to Frankie
Mr. Zeemo's coming into town
in about six days
to pick up his first payment.
He's never been to Vegas
and he wants to look over
his newest acquisition.
What would happen to Frankie
if, uh, he didn't
give Zeemo his "skim"?
( chuckles )
No, Frankie's not that dumb.
Miles, are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Well, it depends
on what you're thinking.
All we have to do
is see to it that Mr. Zeemo
doesn't see a penny
of that money.
Are you talking
about robbing the casino?
That's what I was thinking.
Isn't it
dangerous?
Stealing from the mob?
You bet it is.
You get caught,
and I kiss the world good-bye.
Well, then the trick is
not to get caught.
You guys are nuts,
you know that?
Besides, the money's
kept in a safe.
What kind of safe?
I don't know-- it's
in the count room.
And there's a guard
outside the door 24 hours a day.
And even if you did get past him
there's still
that little problem
of the two count men inside.
I'll get a look at the safe.
We'll figure out
a way to take
out the guard.
And the count men.
And anything else
that comes along.
Then we're agreed?
BASHIR:
Absolutely.
I'm in.
Me, too.
Sure.
Okay.
Let's do it!
Wait a minute.
Let me get this straight.
You're going
to knock over the casino
and swipe a cool million
from the mob?
Vic...
you want your lounge back
or not?
Deal me in.
Have you ever seen
a prettier shade of green?
Looks like you had
a profitable night.
And the night's not over.
Is that for me
or, uh...
am I just keeping
it warm for you?
It's all yours, baby
and there's more
where that came from.
I'll, uh, take
your word for it.
What are you looking at?!
Nothing.
Just keep counting.
After you, sweetheart.
Are you sure you didn't
go to high school in Asheville
North Carolina?
Yeah. I'm positive.
That's funny.
You look just like the captain
of our football team.
I had such a crush on him.
Well, um, actually, I, um...
I did play a little football.
I knew it.
You have the body of an athlete.
You call this a cheese-steak?
Hmm?
I wouldn't feed this
to my parole officer.
Excuse me,
uh, Cicci...
uh, could I have
a word with you?
Just a second, please.
Now, I want
a real cheese-steak
and I don't care
if you gotta fly to
Philadelphia to get it.
A guy could starve to death
in this town.
Ezri...
this is
Tony Cicci.
Nice to meet you.
Oh...
pleasure's all mine.
Ezri's new
in town.
She needs a job.
I'm a very good waitress.
Aah...
you wouldn't happen to have
a slice of pizza
on you, would you?
No, but... I could go
to the kitchen and get you one.
Aah! That chef wouldn't
know a good pizza
if it hit him right in the face.
Consider yourself
gainfully employed.
Really?
That's wonderful.
Thanks, Cicci.
I owe you one.
Ah, don't mention it, Stretch.
Maybe one of these days,
you'll show me
that, uh...
I don't believe it.
Take it--
Take it easy, pally.
Take it easy!
I'm not looking for trouble.
Well, that's a relief.
I'm here to see Frankie.
I want to try to work
things out with him.
You know, let
bygones be bygones.
VIC:
Frankie, I'm dying here.
The Sands, the Dunes, the D.I.--
no one will even return my call.
Tell me something
I don't know.
There's got to be a way for us
to bury the hatchet.
I already did...
in your head.
Frankie, you want me
to beg, I'll beg.
Give me a chance
to make things right.
I know people-- people
with dough, high rollers.
I could bring them
into the
casino.
What?
You want to be my shill?
I'm talking
about people
who can drop ten, 20,
30 big ones a night.
Give him what he
wants, Frankie.
I can't take much
more of his whining.
Bring in a couple
of players...
then we'll talk.
That's all I ask.
Let me buy you a drink.
I don't drink
with losers.
Come on, dollface...
let's, uh, warm up
the poker table.
Welcome back.
You're in charge of what?
Of distracting
the guard
so that we can sneak someone
into the count room.
Kasidy, I can't believe
you're involved in this thing.
The whole thing
is ridiculous.
I guess that means you're
not going to wish me luck.
And you're telling me
that virtually
my entire senior staff
is a part of this nonsense.
You're supposed to
help your friends
when they're in trouble
and Vic, hologram or
not, is in trouble.
Not that I expect
you to care.
Look, this is not
about Vic Fontaine.
Then what is
your problem?
You want to know?
You really want to know
what my problem is?
I'll tell you:
Las Vegas, 1962.
That's my problem.
In 1962, black people
weren't very welcome there.
Oh, sure, they could be
performers or janitors
but customers-- never.
Maybe that's the way
it was in the real Vegas
but that is not
the way it is at Vic's.
I have never
felt uncomfortable there
and neither has Jake.
But don't you see?
That's the lie.
In 1962,
the Civil Rights Movement
was still in its infancy.
It wasn't an easy time
for our people
and I'm not going
to pretend that it was.
Baby...
I know that Vic's
isn't a totally accurate
representation
of the way things were,
but it isn't meant to be.
It shows us the way
things could have been.
The way they
should have been.
We cannot ignore
the truth about the past.
Going to Vic's isn't
going to make us forget
who we are or
where we came from.
What it does is reminds us
that we are no longer bound
by any limitations...
except the ones we
impose on ourselves.
What about Worf?
KIRA:
Oh, he'll never agree to it.
There's
always Quark.
I'm not sure
he'd help.
He thinks of you
as his competition.
( knocking at door )
I'll get it.
Better get this
out of sight.
EZRI:
There's one
little problem.
We're still
one man short.
BASHIR:
We need a high roller
with Vic
at the craps table.
Someone to gather
a crowd
keep attention away
from the count room.
Otherwise,
the whole plan
falls apart.
And we certainly can't
let that happen.
Now...
exactly what do you
need me to do?
Let's go over it
one more time.
Do we have to?
Everyone knows
what they have to do, right?
It's all pretty
simple, really.
Hey, far be it from me
to tell Starfleet officers
how to do their jobs.
Well, robbing casinos
isn't part of
any Starfleet
job description I've ever read.
We can't afford
to make any mistakes.
And we're not going to.
Take us through it again.
You got it, pally.
It all begins with you
keeping Frankie Eyes
away from the casino
and the count room.
Meanwhile, the Captain and I
will be laying down
some heavy bread
over at the craps table--
enough to draw a crowd.
SISKO:
Where are we going to get
that kind of money?
VIC:
I put a little away
for a rainy day.
Now, each night
at precisely 11:45...
SISKO:
Al, one of the count men,
takes a break to call home.
He never varies his routine.
He's gone for eight minutes
every night.
VIC:
During those eight minutes,
Howard, the other count man
has a martini brought in.
EZRI:
That's where I come in
but first, I make a stop
at poker table three
where I hand a drink to Julian.
BASHIR:
And I slip a few drops
of ipecac into Howard's.
EZRI:
After which
I continue on
to the count room.
I set the tray down and leave.
VIC:
Once Ezri's out
of the count room...
KASIDY:
I go running up to the guard
and tell him Chief O'Brien
has stolen my chips.
VIC:
Do whatever you need to do
to keep him distracted
and don't be afraid
to turn on the waterworks.
And, Chief, you play innocent.
O'BRIEN:
I am innocent.
I've never seen this woman
before in my life.
VIC:
That's the ticket.
Now, remember, the two of you
have to keep that guard
away from the door
for at least two minutes.
BASHIR:
Once he takes a sip
of his drink
Howard will come flying out of
that count room at warp speed.
NOG:
Which is where I come in.
VIC:
You and those fabulous
Ferengi ears of yours.
NOG:
And once
I've opened the safe...
ODO:
You'll need someplace
to put all that money.
VIC:
You're going to be surprised
how much
a million bucks weighs.
ODO:
I think I can handle it.
VIC:
When you walk into the casino,
don't talk to anyone.
Don't even look at anyone,
and whatever you do, don't
run.
Just head for the exit
and dump the cash
in the garbage cans outside.
With no money,
there's no skim for Mr. Zeemo
and old Frankie
becomes yesterday's news.
BASHIR:
Then everything
returns to normal
and we pop open the champagne.
Music to my ears, pally.
Eight minutes.
That's how long we have
to get into the count room
open the safe, grab the money,
and then get out again.
I bet we do it in five.
When do we pull off the caper?
The sooner the better.
Zeemo's due in two days.
Then we have no choice.
We go tomorrow night.
( chuckling ):
Hey.
Crazy.
That was fast.
It has to be.
Two minutes, 14 seconds.
I've got to do
a lot better than that.
Right.
Go.
( Sisko chuckles )
Better finish
getting dressed.
It's almost time.
I'm telling you, Morn
something's going
on in Vic's
that we don't
know about.
Looking good as usual,
dollface.
I'm glad you like
what you see.
Only wish
I could see more.
Well, you know
what they say.
"Good things come
to those who wait."
Who are "they"
and how much of you
have they seen?
I never kiss and tell.
I bet you don't.
Whoo! 19!
Let's see
if you can beat that.
23. You're busted.
( chuckling )
A vodka martini.
Stirred, not shaken.
Right away, sir.
The winner is 17 black.
SISKO:
10,000.
CROUPIER:
Good luck, sir.
We're coming out.
Make your bets.
Here they come.
C&amp;E. High-
low bets.
$100?
Too much?
You're supposed to
be a high roller
so start rolling.
Make it, uh, 2,000.
( growling )
2,000.
What do you say
we blow some of my money
at the crap tables?
Maybe later.
Right now, I want you
to buy me a drink.
We can play footsies
under the table.
"Footsies"?
I guess that's a start.
We have lift-off.
Oh! I'm so sorry!
Don't worry about it.
You're too kind.
CROUPIER:
Coming out, now.
New shooter.
Here's where things
get interesting.
Come on...
seven!
You're not Howard.
He's out with the flu.
Oh. Well, this drink
must be yours, then.
I'm not thirsty.
But...
Hey
you're making me lose count.
Sorry.
You mind if I drink that?
I've been on my feet
for hours
and I could really use
a little pick-me-up.
That's about the saddest
story I ever heard.
CROUPIER:
Winner seven, twice.
Shooter's on a roll.
Make your bets.
Let it ride.
We're coming out.
Let it ride,
let it ride.
CROUPIER:
He's got a hand going.
Ten dollars on the 11.
You have to help me.
That man, that man right there--
he stole a stack of my chips.
Hey, you!
Stop right there!
Who, me?
The lady says
you stole her chips.
I did no such thing.
Liar!
I'm telling you
he took them.
You're a thief.
You're drunk.
I am not!
Hey, hey.
Let's just calm
down here, okay?
KASIDY:
Not until I
get my money!
O'BRIEN:
What money?
KASIDY:
The money
you stole!
O'BRIEN:
I told you, I never
touched your money!
KASIDY:
Liar!
( gagging )
( gurgling rustle )
Uh-oh.
What do you
mean, "uh-oh"?
We don't have
time for "uh-oh."
The safe-- it has
an auto-relock tumbler.
Kira didn't mention anything
about an auto-relock tumbler.
Well, she obviously
didn't know about it.
I'm not going
to have enough time.
Keep working.
This is the hand
that shook the hand
of Bugsy Siegel.
The man that
built Las Vegas.
I'm telling you
he was a visionary.
And is there even one statue
of the guy in this town?
There's no justice.
You can say that again.
Sure you don't want to
play the tables for awhile?
I'm perfectly content
right here.
Well, who am I to
argue with a lady?
What are you standing
around for? Arrest him.
I told you he took $200
worth of chips from me.
Well, how come
I only got five bucks on me?
Don't believe him.
I'm telling you, this broad
ain't playing
with a full deck.
KASIDY:
And just what is that
supposed to mean?
O'BRIEN:
What do you
think it means?
( cheering and yelling )
Beginner's luck.
For the dealer!
Six minutes.
I wonder what's
taking them so long?
I got to go.
I'm running late.
This Frankie Eyes...
( grunting in frustration )
You in some
kind of hurry?
Me?
You keep staring at that watch.
Really?
I hadn't noticed.
And your drink.
You haven't touched it.
Oh, well,
the night is young.
I've got to pace myself.
Pace yourself?
For what?
Frankie
there's someone here
to see you.
I'm busy.
MAN:
You don't
look busy.
Mr. Zeemo.
We weren't expecting you
until tomorrow.
I'm early.
Any problem with that?
No, not at all.
Sit down.
Have a drink.
We'll have a
drink later.
Where's the, uh...
where's the
count room?
Follow me.
Mr. Zeemo?
It's a great honor
to meet you.
I know.
Frankie has told me
so much about you.
Frankie.
Yeah?
The money, Frankie.
Right this way.
Let's go.
Come on.
Nog, it's been eight minutes.
We're running
out of time.
( handle rattles )
( frustrated growl )
Yeah?
Okay. Yeah, sure.
I fold.
Excuse me.
Your name's Al, right?
Who wants to know?
Frankie Eyes.
Frankie Eyes?
He's waiting for you.
Out back.
For what? I
didn't do nothing.
Then you have nothing
to worry about.
You gotta be kidding me.
Now what?
Zeemo.
He's a day early.
Keep playing.
I'll try to stall him.
Nina?
Is that you?
Who's this?
Nobody. Hey, Vic,
take a walk, huh?
Where you been
keeping yourself, baby?
Do I know you?
Do you know me?
Don't you remember
that week in Miami?
You ever see what she
looks like in a bikini?
Ooh, mama mia.
When were you
in Miami?
I don't know
what he's talking about.
Who's this, your grandpa?
Frankie.
Cicci.
Now you done it.
Bury him.
So long, sucker.
Frankie
I'm waiting
for the money!
Right this way.
Tonight everybody's a winner!
( handle rattles )
What's this?
What's going on?
( squealing and laughing )
( clicking )
( chuckles )
Piece of cake.
Can I go now?
You aren't going anywhere.
Don't let him leave.
Charlie.
Over here.
Take this, uh,
gentleman to security.
But I wanted you
to handle this.
I'm afraid I can't
leave my post.
Charlie, strip search.
Strip search?!
Uh...
( sobbing )
There, there.
It's not worth all that.
KASIDY:
I needed
that money
t-to buy a gift
for my mother.
Funny way to run a casino.
What are you waiting for,
Frankie?
Why don't you show Mr. Zeemo
the count room?
Well, you heard the lady.
I'm telling you, Mr. Zeemo
buying this casino
was the smartest move
you ever made.
We're making money
hand over fist.
I just hope you brought
a big enough briefcase.
Where's my money?
Huh?!
( sultry striptease music
playing )
Now, that's more like it.
ODO:
Say good-bye
to Frankie Eyes.
KIRA:
You can tell
your friend Felix
that we shut the lid
on his jack-in-the-box.
With pleasure.
Ladies and gentlemen
the bubbly is on me.
BASHIR:
Thanks, Vic.
ODO:
Hear, hear.
Where have you been?
I don't want
to talk about it.
Next time you two fight
the battle of the Alamo
count me in.
Coonskin cap
and all.
You've got it, pally.
To the best friends
a hologram ever had.
BASHIR:
Hear, hear.
O'BRIEN: Cheers.
I owe you-- big time.
BASHIR:
Cheers, Vic.
EZRI:
Cheers.
Okay, fellas
let's do it.
( music begins )
Captain?
Will you join me?
( whispers ):
What?
♪ Out of the tree of life
I just picked me a plum ♪
♪ You came along
and everything started to hum ♪
♪ still, it's a real good bet
the best is yet to come ♪
♪ The best is yet to come
and, babe, won't it be fine? ♪
♪ You think you've seen the sun,
but you ain't seen it shine ♪
♪ Wait till the warm-up's
underway ♪
♪ Wait till our lips have met ♪
♪ Wait till you see
that sunshine day ♪
♪ You ain't seen nothin' yet ♪
♪ The best is
yet to come ♪
♪ And, babe, won't
it be fine? ♪
♪ The best is yet to come,
come the day you're mine ♪
♪ Wait till your charms are ripe
for these arms to surround ♪
♪ You think you've
flown before ♪
♪ But you ain't
left the ground ♪
♪ Now, wait till you're locked
in my embrace ♪
♪ Wait till I
draw you near ♪
♪ Wait till you see
that sunshine place ♪
♪ Ain't nothin'
like it here ♪
♪ The best is yet to come ♪
♪ And, babe,
won't it be fine? ♪
♪ The best
is yet to come ♪
♪ The best is yet to come ♪
♪ Come the day you're mine. ♪