All right, next item.
Item seven,
warbird repair and maintenance.
Senator?
Repairs on our ships
have continually been delayed
in favor of Klingon
and Federation vessels.
The Dividices
and the Genorex have been
waiting almost three weeks
while more than
a dozen Klingon ships
have been given first priority.
Well, I make up
the repair schedule
according to my assessment
of which ships have
the greatest need.
Odd that the Klingons
seem to always have
the greatest need.
They are usually more damaged
because Klingon warships
are relentless
in pressing home their attack.
"Reckless" would be
another way of putting it.
The fight must be taken
to the enemy.
We cannot win this war...
All right, we're not here
to debate combat tactics.
Chief, how soon can you have
those warbirds
into a docking bay?
Well, I suppose I could
bring them in tomorrow.
But that would mean delaying
repairs to the Hornet
and the Rotarran.
Somebody's going
to have to explain
to General Martok
why his flagship was bumped.
Worf, you just volunteered
for that assignment.
This brings up the
question of shore leave.
At the moment, we have the crews
from two Klingon ships
on the station.
I'd rather not have that
many Klingons and Romulans
on the Promenade
at the same time.
We'll forgo shore leave
until the Klingons depart.
Our soldiers are professionals.
They're here to fight
not to get drunk in Quark's.
All right.
That's it for today then.
Same time next week?
Oh, sorry, Senator.
You'll be attending
that conference
on Romulus, won't you?
Yes, but Subcommander Velal
will be here in my place.
Fine. Have a safe trip.
Thank you.
Ah, yes.
Romulus...
how well I remember it.
You'll find the predominant
color to be gray...
the buildings, the
clothes, the people.
Did you know that the Romulan
heart itself is gray?
It's true.
And altogether appropriate
for such an unimaginative race.
I take it you didn't enjoy
your brief stint on Romulus.
You were... posing
as a gardener, weren't you?
It was one of the few instances
where my cover
was more enjoyable
than the actual assignment.
What was the assignment anyway?
I'm afraid
I can't talk about that.
Back to the subject at hand.
What would your role be
at this conference?
Well, I'll be giving a talk
on Dominion biogenic weapons
chairing a seminar
on ketracel-white
and attending a meeting
on a proposal
to transfer 25
Federation hospital ships
over to Romulan control.
How dull.
Sorry to disappoint.
Admiral Ross and his staff
will be discussing the
"exciting" military issues.
I see.
I-I trust that
Starfleet Intelligence
will be sending someone along
to make good use
of this opportunity.
What do you mean?
Well, isn't it obvious?
This is a golden opportunity
to gather intelligence
on Romulan intentions
and military capabilities.
They're our allies, Garak.
And with any luck
this could be the beginning
of an entirely new friendship
between our peoples.
The eternal optimist.
Guilty as charged.
How sad.
I must tell you,
I'm disappointed
at hearing you mouth
the usual platitudes
of peace and friendship
regarding an implacable foe
like the Romulans.
But I live in hope that one day
you'll come to see this universe
for what it truly is
rather than what
you'd wish it to be.
Well, I shall endeavor
to become more cynical
with each passing day.
Look gift horses
squarely in the mouth
and find clouds in
every silver lining.
If only you meant it.
Lights.
Sloan.
Hello, Doctor.
It's good to see you.
I hope you're well rested.
Section 31 has
an assignment for you.
You're taking quite a risk.
I could have a security team
here in 30 seconds.
I suspect
you'd be unable to communicate
with anyone
outside of this room.
I could scream for help.
Possible
but uncharacteristic.
I mean, screaming for help...
that's... that's
too undignified for you.
But don't let me stop you.
I enjoy being wrong.
What do you want?
I told you.
You have an assignment.
I don't work for you.
You passed the test.
You were accepted
into the organization.
I didn't ask to be accepted.
You were nevertheless.
And now it's time to go to work.
I'm sure you're dying to know
what your mission is
but you won't give me
the satisfaction
of admitting it.
So I'll just tell you.
Lucky me.
Section 31
is extremely interested
in this conference of yours.
However, the Tal Shiar
will be handling
the security arrangements
so we'll have virtually
no chance
of using any technical assets
to gather intelligence.
As a result, we'll be forced
to rely on organic assets...
like you.
Your mission is to gather data
about the Romulan leadership.
In essence, we want you
to take the pulse
of their government.
No pun intended.
You want me to spy on an ally?
To evaluate an ally.
And a temporary ally at that.
Now, I say that, because
when the war is over
the following will happen
in short order...
the Dominion will be forced
back to the Gamma Quadrant.
The Cardassian Empire
will be occupied.
The Klingon Empire will spend
the next ten years recovering
from the war and won't pose
a serious threat to anyone.
That leaves two powers to vie
for control of the Quadrant...
the Federation and the Romulans.
This war isn't over
and you're already
planning for the next.
Well put.
I hope your report
is equally succinct.
How many times do I have
to tell you, Sloan?
I don't work for you.
You will.
It's in your nature.
You are a man
who loves secrets...
medical, personal, fictional.
And I am a man of secrets.
You want to know what I know
and the only way to do that
is to accept the assignment.
Whoa! Easy, Julian.
What's going on?
Odo's checked
all the security logs.
There's no indication
of how Sloan got aboard
or where he went.
I can't say I'm surprised.
From what we've seen of them
Section 31 is very meticulous
in covering its tracks.
I had a conversation with
Admiral Ross this afternoon.
He and I both agree
that the Romulan conference
is too important to cancel.
What about me?
Starfleet Command has promised
to send the expert
on Dominion biogenic weapons
and ketracel-white
to the conference.
Since that's you, you go.
And we want you to carry out
your assignment.
Make a few discreet observations
on the Romulan leadership
and then wait for Sloan
to contact you again.
Somehow, I don't
think giving Sloan
any information is a good idea.
That was my instinct as well,
but after talking to Ross
I think we might have
an opportunity here
we can turn to our advantage.
Officially, Starfleet Command
has said that they are appalled
at the very notion
that an organization like
Section 31 might exist
and that they plan
to get to the bottom
of this entire business.
And unofficially?
They have quietly
pushed the investigation aside.
Which means either they
don't take Section 31 seriously
or... someone at Starfleet
Command is protecting them.
Either way, we now have a chance
to get someone inside
and I think I want to take it.
So you want me to play along?
Pretend that I've decided
to work for Sloan after all?
Exactly.
When he contacts you to find out
what you learned
at the conference
make it seem like
you've reluctantly come around
to his way of thinking.
Let him believe
that he has seduced you
into helping him.
Well, that shouldn't
be too difficult.
Sloan thinks
I'm already so tempted
that I barely can see straight.
Well, listen, I better pack.
The Bellerophon leaves
in three hours.
One more thing, Doctor.
Remember this isn't a game.
Section 31 is very dangerous.
If Sloan even suspects
that you are really
working for us...
I understand.
Good hunting.
A glass of Romulan ale,
Doctor?
Thank you, Senator.
The trading embargo
has been officially lifted
if you were wondering.
It hadn't crossed
my mind, actually.
To one of the many benefits
of the alliance.
Need a medical team, sir?
No, thank you.
Don't tell me this is
your first glass of Romulan ale.
Well, it was...
ille... illegal.
That never stopped
most of your colleagues.
I know... I was probably
one of the few officers
in the fleet
who didn't indulge occasionally.
Would you like something else?
No, no, I'll manage.
That's the spirit, sir.
Never say die.
What an odd expression.
What does it mean?
It's a line
from an old Earth poem.
Forgive me for interrupting.
I couldn't help overhearing
and etymology is
one of my hobbies.
The, uh, phrase "never
say die" is originally
from a 19th century poem
based on Shakespeare's
Merchant of Venice.
Now, it's since passed
into the vernacular
as a, as an exhortation
never to give up
no matter the cost.
Interesting.
Wendell Greer,
Assistant Director
UFP Department of Cartography.
It's a pleasure.
Admiral William Ross,
Senator Cretak.
Admiral... Senator.
And Dr. Julian Bashir.
Ah, the physician
from Deep Space 9.
I was hoping to meet you.
I have so many questions
about the Bajoran sector...
navigational anomalies,
the transport patterns...
Could you spare a moment?
Unless I'm interrupting.
Not at all.
Try to play your cards
a little closer
to your vest, Doctor.
You're lucky they didn't see
that look of shock on your face.
You managed to get yourself
attached to this delegation.
Why do you need me?
All in due time.
Now you have a lot of work to do
before we arrive at Romulus.
There's a padd
in your quarters... read it.
I'll join you at 2200.
Well, Mr. Greer certainly
has his ducks in a row.
According to the Department
of Cartography
he's been a low-level bureaucrat
for almost 15 years.
Well, it doesn't surprise me
he has a solid cover story, sir.
But I think it's too dangerous
to allow him to participate
in the conference
or even set foot on Romulus.
We don't know what he's up to.
On the other hand,
if we move against him now
we lose any hope
of penetrating Section 31.
His access at this conference
will be limited
to a few low-level
briefings and seminars.
It shouldn't be too hard
keeping tabs on him.
If Sloan's here...
it suggests something
more important
than a simple intelligence-
gathering mission.
He's up to something
and it's imperative that we
know what that something is.
We go forward.
Next.
Neral... formerly Proconsul
now Praetor
of the Romulan Star Empire.
Neral's ascension
to the top post
was confirmed
by the Continuing Committee
a little over a year ago.
His immediate family
was killed in a Klingon raid
approximately 25 years ago.
His interests include
sociology and archaeology.
His favorite food
is Delvan pudding
and his pet set'leth's name
is... Pensho.
Very good.
Total recall is a useful
attribute for an operative.
Koval... chairman
of the Tal Shiar.
Section 31 believes that he
was involved in the death
of Vice Admiral Fujisaki
last year
but there's no proof.
The proof is buried
somewhere in Koval's
personal database
which puts it
out of our reach for now.
But believe me, Doctor,
the Deputy Chief
of Starfleet Intelligence
doesn't just die
of food poisoning.
I have to give him credit,
though.
It was a textbook operation.
No sign of foul play
and certainly no sign
of Romulan involvement.
It was very tidy.
Koval's political status?
Ambiguous.
He hasn't been elevated
to the Continuing Committee
which is usually a given
for the head of the Tal Shiar.
His nomination has
probably been held up
because of his opposition
to the Federation alliance
which is supported
by the majority
on the Committee.
Which, in turn, opens the door
for your friend, Senator Cretak.
She's an advocate
of the alliance
and she's been lobbying
for this open seat.
There is another rumor
about Koval
which is not contained
in his file.
We've heard he's ill...
something called Tuvan Syndrome.
I'm familiar with it.
It's a neurological disease
which affects mainly Vulcans,
Romulans and Rigelians.
It's degenerative,
and incurable at present.
If Koval is ill,
he'll try to hide it.
It's a weakness, and
one that could hamper
his chances of being
appointed to the Committee.
Is that what I'm here for?
A diagnosis?
What's the matter, Sloan?
Doesn't Section 31
have its own doctors?
Our physicians weren't
genetically enhanced.
They need equipment
to make a diagnosis...
equipment that the Romulans
won't permit at this conference.
I'm incapable
of making a diagnosis
by simply looking at a man.
Oh, your genetically-
enhanced friends
determined that Gul Damar
killed a woman
just by watching him
give a political speech.
I'm sure you can do
better than that.
You're going to make a move
against Koval, aren't you?
You're going to find
a way to use his illness
to keep him off the Committee.
I suppose it would be
naive of me to point out
that interfering
in the internal affairs
of a sovereign power
is explicitly forbidden
by the Federation Charter.
Without confirming or denying
your speculation
I will say
that if Koval comes to power
it'd be a disaster
for the Federation.
He'll argue for the Romulans
to abrogate the alliance
and negotiate a separate peace
with the Dominion
and I don't think
I need to tell you
what that would do
to the course of the war.
You can't justify that
by manipulating...
Let's make a deal, Doctor...
I'll spare you the ends-
justify-the-means speech
and you spare me
the we-must-do-
what's-right speech.
You and I are not going to see
eye to eye on this subject
so I suggest
we stop discussing it.
This mission is reconnaissance.
We are not going
to be called upon
to do anything other than that.
Now, why don't you
get some rest?
We'll be in orbit
of Romulus by 0600
and you will need to have
your wits about you.
Here you are, sir.
Dr. Julian Bashir?
Yes.
I understand
you were the officer
who first identified
the biogenic weapon
known as the Quickening.
That's right...
on Boranis III,
in the Gamma Quadrant.
I don't believe
we've been introduced.
Koval.
Well, it's a pleasure
to meet you.
Why?
Well, you've got me there.
It's just a simple
form of expression, I suppose.
And like most human expressions
completely devoid of meaning.
Can the Dominion's Quickening
virus be replicated?
We've had a little difficulty
in, uh, recreating
the exact RNA sequence
of the virus
which is why we've been
unable to develop a vaccine.
However, there are alternate
methods of making vaccines...
I'm not interested
in the vaccine.
I'm interested in the virus.
Do you know how to introduce
the Quickening
into a population?
Basically.
Good.
I look forward
to hearing your lecture.
You're going to make
a very fine operative, Doctor.
I beg your pardon?
The Chairman of the Tal Shiar
rarely speaks
with anyone in public...
much less someone
wearing that uniform.
Starfleet Intelligence
should recruit you immediately.
What makes you think I'm not
working for them already?
Somehow, it wouldn't surprise me
if half the people in this room
turned out to be operatives.
You are joking.
It may be impolitic to say this
but there are those who believe
the alliance is merely a...
momentary truce.
And are you one of them?
Well, I could ask you
the same thing.
Well, in my case,
it's a firm "no"
but you've answered
my question...
with a question.
I try not to predict
the future.
What about Chairman Koval?
You tell me.
You just spoke with him.
That's more than I've
done in six months.
I take it you two
don't get along.
We have different views.
Which are?
State secrets.
Naturally.
This is an adult female
inhabitant of Boranis III.
The markings on the face
are typical of a humanoid
who's been infected
by the disease
but who has not yet entered
the terminal stage.
In this next photograph
you can tell by the necrotic
nature of the lesions
that the patient has, indeed,
entered the terminal stage
of the disease.
This is also marked
by an increase
in leukocyte production.
Thank you, Doctor.
Excellent.
Thank you.
Very enlightening.
You almost made it
comprehensible.
Next time, I'll do the lecture
with hand puppets just for you.
Thank you very much.
I'm glad to see you still
have your sense of humor.
I trust you noticed who was
sitting in the front row.
Yes. He came to see me this
morning between sessions.
He wanted to know more
about the Quickening...
specifically, if I knew
how to replicate the virus
and how to introduce it
into a population.
What did you think
of his health?
Didn't you hear
what I just said?
I heard you.
Koval wants to get his
hands on the Quickening.
That's not news to me...
that the head of the Tal Shiar
is interested
in biogenic weapons.
Pull your head out of the sand
and take a look around, Doctor.
These are not nice people
we're dealing with here.
Now answer my question.
His eyelids were
slightly displaced.
He had a noticeable weakness
in the facial muscles...
probably the result
of a compromised
neuromuscular function...
and his respiration
was somewhat irregular.
Bottom line.
He may have Tuvan Syndrome.
But if he does,
it's in the very early stages.
How long does he have?
If his case fits the profile
he will start experiencing
a loss of motor skills
in ten to 15 years...
with a life expectancy
in the 20 to 25-year range.
Are there instances
in which the disease
accelerates without warning?
It happens, but in less than
five percent of the cases.
Is there anything that could
trigger the acceleration?
You know... I don't know
what you're asking me.
Never mind.
Thank you, Doctor.
You've been very helpful.
This is unbelievable.
Let's put aside for the moment
that he's contemplating
the murder
of a high-ranking official.
What in the hell makes him think
that the next head
of the Tal Shiar
would be any better than Koval?
Well, Sloan's more
concerned with who gets
the empty seat on the
Continuing Committee.
He's hoping
that Cretak gets that.
Well, I sort of agree
with him there.
Cretak, for all her abrasiveness
is at least a patriot.
What makes her any different
from Koval?
If you saw the reports
from Starfleet Intelligence
that I see, you would
never ask that question.
Koval would like nothing better
than to see the Romulan
banner waving over Earth.
Believe me, Doctor,
Chairman Koval is not someone
we want to see
at the Praetor's right hand.
I'll have Sloan confined
to his quarters immediately
but that may not
solve our problem.
Sir?
Has it occurred to you
that you and Sloan may not
be the only ones here
working for Section 31?
For all we know,
he has a confederate
somewhere in the delegation.
Sloan did say that our mission
would be strictly
reconnaissance...
that we wouldn't be called
upon to do anything else.
That could suggest
another operative...
someone whose mission isn't
limited to reconnaissance.
If that's true,
it could be anyone...
even a member of
the Bellerophon crew.
Or a Romulan.
What?
Sir, I believe Sloan
has an accomplice
here... on Romulus.
What makes you say that?
Two things.
First, Sloan has
too much information
on the inner workings
of their government...
too many insights into
their political process.
Second,
Sloan's plan is to kill Koval
while making it appear to be
an accelerated case
of Tuvan Syndrome.
Now, the only way to do that
would be to expose Koval
to a short burst
of nadion radiation.
The simplest plan would be to
maneuver him near a phaser relay
and surreptitiously
irradiate him.
Now, since I doubt very much
that Sloan is going to have
the chance to do that
it stands to reason someone else
is going to have to.
A Romulan?
Exactly.
Sir, Sloan may have already
gotten things underway.
We have to warn them.
And how am I supposed to explain
Section 31 to the Romulans?
All hell would break loose
if they hear
that there's a rogue
Federation agency running around
plotting assassinations.
It could bring
the alliance down.
Besides, all we have
is speculation
- at this point.
- Admiral...
The answer is no.
After I have Sloan arrested,
I'll break radio silence
and inform Starfleet Command
of the situation.
Your orders are to sit tight
and do nothing
until you hear from me.
Aye, sir.
I don't know.
Jepella said she went
in to deliver a report
and found him slumped
over his desk.
Do they have any idea
what happened?
Dr. Frame said it looked
like an aneurysm
but they're still running tests.
An aneurysm.
I saw the Admiral this morning.
He looked fine.
They say that's
the way it happens.
Which Admiral are
you talking about?
Uh, Admiral Ross, sir.
He collapsed at his desk.
Where is he?
Sick Bay.
Hey.
I can't trust anybody
aboard the Bellerophon.
And I can't contact DS9.
For security reasons, there's
been a communications blackout.
Senator, I have no one
else to turn to.
I need your help.
To do what?
I have reason to believe
that Sloan has an accomplice
within the Romulan government.
Someone who's going to help him
carry out this assassination.
Koval has been saying
there's a traitor in the Senate.
Someone working for
Starfleet Intelligence.
Section 31 isn't part
of Starfleet Intelligence.
They are Federation
citizens working
to advance your interests.
That makes them
your responsibility.
You're absolutely right.
That's why I'm doing everything
I can to stop them.
I'm trying to convince Sloan
that Koval doesn't
have Tuvan Syndrome
but he may have already asked
his accomplice to proceed.
So if we want to be sure
to stop this assassination
we have to find Sloan's
Romulan accomplice.
And you expect me
to find this traitor.
Sloan said something about Koval
having a personal database.
It stands to reason
that it contains a list
of potential suspects.
Now, is there any possible way
you can get me
a copy of this database
so that I can run
an analysis of...
You are asking me to hand
over secret documents.
I'm asking you to put aside
three centuries of mistrust
between our peoples
and help me stop a murder.
Senator, if we can't reach out
and bridge the gulf
that is between us
if we can't trust each other,
a man will die
and we will be
partially responsible.
I need your help.
Please.
You wanted to see me, Doctor?
Yes.
I'm not convinced that Koval is
suffering from Tuvan Syndrome.
His symptoms could be the result
of any number of different
health problems.
You didn't say that before.
Well, I'm not an expert
on Romulan physiology.
Most of my knowledge
on Tuvan Syndrome
comes from studies
done on Vulcan patients.
I thought Vulcans
and Romulans
were virtually identical.
Yes, but there are
some important
genetic differences.
And the more I study
the available data
on Romulan physiology
the less sure I am that
my diagnosis was correct.
How could you find out
for sure?
The best way would be
to do an examination
but I hardly think
he'll agree to that.
What if you obtained
a sample of his skin cells?
Could you run an analysis?
Probably.
But how do you propose...
We'll treat your palm
with a microcellular adhesive.
The next time
you shake his hand
you'll get your sample.
All right.
Mr. Chairman.
What a pleasure
to see you again.
I'd be very happy to resume
our discussion on the Quickening
before this conference
is adjourned.
I believe you answered
all my questions, Doctor.
Well, I'm glad
to have been able to help.
Doctor, I would like to have
a word with you
on another matter.
In private.
Of course.
I believe
the Lecture Hall's empty.
We have other, more comfortable
facilities available,
if you please.
Sit down.
I can assure you that you
will be sitting in that chair
one way or the other, Doctor.
Now we'll have our private talk.
What shall we talk about?
Why you're really on Romulus.
Who you're working for,
and, of course
who's helping you.
Don't worry...
I won't waste your time
with pointless questions.
This can be painful or not.
That's up to you, Doctor.
Either way, I will know
what you know.
It appears that your brain's
neurocellular structure
is not susceptible
to our scanning techniques.
Evidently a result
of the genetic enhancements
made to your parietal cortex.
Sorry.
I do have other methods
at my disposal
but it would save everyone
a great deal of trouble
if you would simply tell
me what I want to know.
You haven't asked me
any questions yet.
I think you know what
I'm interested in.
Who are you working for?
Why are you here?
Bring him.
Dr. Julian Bashir.
You are appearing before
the Continuing Committee
of the Romulan people.
Any statements will be made
part of the official record.
Senator Cretak
is charged with attempting
to access a Tal Shiar database
without proper authorization.
The Senator has told the
Committee a remarkable story.
Since you are a key figure
in her story
we are most eager to hear
your version of events.
What I am about to say
may be shocking.
It may even damage the relations
between our two peoples
but it's the truth.
A few days ago,
I became aware of a plot
to assassinate Chairman Koval.
It was conceived of
by a man known to me
only as "Sloan."
He works for an organization
called Section 31.
They see themselves
as protecting the interests
of the Federation
although they have absolutely
no official standing.
Once I realized what Sloan
was attempting to do
I contacted Senator Cretak
in order to enlist her aid
in stopping him.
Why her?
I had no one else to turn to.
I was unable to contact
Deep Space 9
and I couldn't trust anybody
aboard the Bellerophon.
But you felt that you could
trust a Romulan Senator?
Yes.
For all our differences
I do respect her.
Continue.
For reasons that are
extremely complicated
I came to believe
that there's a traitor
in your government
working for Section 31.
I asked the Senator
to obtain the database
so that we could
expose this person
and prevent the assassination.
Senator Cretak,
why didn't you come to me
with this information?
I was afraid that if word
of this... plot... got out
it would destroy the alliance.
I decided to keep
my own counsel.
I regret that decision.
As well you should, Kimara.
It's an interesting story
but it's not the whole story.
If I may be permitted
to bring in another witness?
Bring in prisoner 527.
Praetor
this is the man
known as "Sloan."
Unlike the Doctor, his mind is
quite susceptible
to our data-retrieval methods.
Under questioning,
he has confirmed
much of what the Doctor
and the Senator have told you
with one
important exception...
there is no Section 31.
Sloan, in fact, works
for Starfleet Intelligence.
Far from being the master
of a rogue agency
he is simply one
of many operatives
in the employ
of the Federation.
He's had a long career.
Most of which
is still unknown to us.
However, there is one
interesting element
that we do know...
he was the protégé
of the late
Vice Admiral Fujisaki.
Sloan did not take
the death of his mentor well.
He came to believe
he was murdered
by the Tal Shiar.
In his eyes, the assassination
of a Starfleet Admiral was
"stepping over the line."
Isn't that the phrase?
After Fujisaki's death, he
was confronted with a dilemma.
How could he seek vengeance
without violating
the Federation's laws?
His answer was
to invent Section 31...
a rogue organization
that answered to no one.
If they killed the head
of the Tal Shiar,
Starfleet Intelligence
would be held blameless.
As the Committee knows
I have been diagnosed
with Tuvan Syndrome.
Sloan became aware
of my condition
and hoped to make my death
look like a sudden
acceleration of the disease.
To do that,
he needed a doctor.
Sloan arranged to recruit
Dr. Bashir into Section 31.
After that, Sloan
bided his time
and waited for an opportunity
to present itself.
He found one when he learned
of this conference.
He then arranged
for Bashir to be invited.
Everything was going perfectly
but then he made
a fatal mistake.
He decided to come
to Romulus himself.
He was unaware that his identity
had become known to us.
Once we recognized him
in the delegation
we knew immediately
that an intelligence
operation was underway.
What I don't understand
is... why.
Why did you come here and take
the risk of being discovered?
I had to make sure
nothing went wrong
and I wanted to watch you die...
You broke the cardinal
rule of our profession.
You allowed business
to become personal.
So there was
an assassination plan?
Most definitely.
As to the involvement
of the Doctor and the Senator
Dr. Bashir may have
intended to kill me
or he may have
intended to save me.
There is no way
to know for certain.
As for Senator Cretak
we all know
she's an ambitious woman.
It is entirely possible,
she would
welcome my death,
especially if it meant
her being elevated
to the Continuing Committee
in my place.
That is a lie, Koval.
I was trying to save your life.
Well, then,
you're simply a fool.
You let a Starfleet Intelligence
officer manipulate you
into committing
an act of treason.
It is the finding
of this Committee that
Senator Cretak has conspired
to commit treason
against the state.
Sentence to be determined
at a later date.
Dr. Bashir will be returned
to the Bellerophon.
Mr. Sloan...
is remanded to the custody
of the Tal Shiar
for further interrogation.
No!
Come in.
Admiral.
Doctor.
Feeling, uh, better, sir?
Much.
Dr. Frame tells me
that I should take it easy
for a few days,
but, uh... paperwork
waits for no man.
What can I do for you?
I have a question.
Where's Sloan?
Sloan's dead.
Admiral... where's Sloan?
If we're going to have
this discussion
then it's off the record.
But before I answer your
question, answer mine.
How did you know?
The man Koval described
was not the same man
who recruited me
into Section 31.
Anyone clever enough
to pull the wool
so completely over my eyes
wouldn't have been caught
by the Romulans so easily.
There had to be
another explanation.
And then I remembered
that you were the one
who planted the idea
in my head
that Sloan had an accomplice.
You were the one who didn't
want to tell the Romulans
that there was
an assassination plot.
You were the one
who issued the orders
preventing me from contacting
Deep Space 9.
And when the time
came to arrest Sloan
you conveniently had an
aneurysm... leaving me alone
with no one to turn to
for help, except Cretak
and as I realized
your involvement
the rest began
to fall into place.
Where is he?
I don't know.
But he's alive...
isn't he?
He was supposed
to be beamed away
a split second
before the phaser beam hit him.
Whether it worked or not,
I couldn't say.
How long has Koval
been working for Starfleet?
He's been providing
the Federation
with critical military
intelligence for over a year.
When he started working
with Section 31, I don't know.
But in any case,
we have our mole...
working for us
at the top levels
of Romulan government.
Good for us.
And what about your friend,
Senator Cretak?
What's going to happen to her?
Dismissed from the Senate...
definitely.
Imprisoned, most likely.
Executed?
I hope not.
You set her up!
She was an innocent woman
and you let Sloan destroy her.
Why?
She believed in the alliance.
She was on our side.
No, she wasn't.
I told you before, Julian...
she's a patriot
which means, if it serves
the interests of the Romulans
to negotiate a separate
peace with the Dominion
Cretak would push that option
and believe me, the Dominion
would like nothing more
than to make a deal with
the Romulans right now.
So Koval becomes your guarantee
that that does not happen
and as a man
who was nearly killed
for his anti-Federation
activities
his recommendation
to stay in the war
becomes all
the more convincing.
That's the general idea.
And how long have you worked
for Section 31?
I don't.
Oh, just a temporary
alliance, is it?
Something like that.
You don't see anything wrong
with what happened, do you?
I don't like it
but I've spent the last
year and a half of my life
ordering young men and
young women to die.
I like that even less.
That's a glib answer
and a cheap way
to avoid the fact
that you've trampled
on the very thing
that those young men and women
are out there dying to protect!
Does that not mean
anything to you?!
Inter arma enim silent leges.
"In time of war,
the law falls silent."
Cicero.
So is that what we have become...
a 24th-century Rome
driven by nothing other
than the certainty
that Caesar can do no wrong?!
This conversation
never happened.
You're dismissed.
Good evening.
Are you expecting applause?
Have you come to take a bow?
I just wanted to say thank you.
For what?
Allowing you to manipulate
me so completely?
For being a decent human being.
That's why we selected you
in the first place, Doctor.
We needed somebody
who wanted to play the game
but who'd only go so far.
When the time came,
you stood your ground.
You did the right thing.
You reached out to an enemy.
You told her the truth.
You tried to stop a murder.
The Federation needs
men like you, Doctor.
Men of conscience.
Men of principle.
Men who can sleep at night.
You're also the reason
Section 31 exists.
Someone has to protect
men like you
from a universe
that doesn't share your sense
of right and wrong.
Should I feel sorry for you?
Should I be weeping
over the burden
you're forced to carry
in order to protect
the rest of us?
It is an honor
to know you, Doctor.
Good night.
Bashir to Security.
Odo here.
Never mind.
My mistake.