SISKO:
There are a few
wild moba trees here
and a creek that runs through
the meadows and into the forest.
Nice spot, huh?
Bajor, right?
The Kendra Province,
just south of the Yolja River.
I was there the other day.
I thought you went to a
conference in Rakantha.
I did, but afterwards
Vedek Oram wanted me
to visit his monastery.
We took a transport
across the mountains.
The sun was
just going down
and the entire valley
was shimmering in the light.
And I said to myself
"This is the place.
This is where I'm going
to build my house."
I've... heard you talk
that way before.
Oh, no, this is not just talk.
As of this morning,
all of this land belongs to me.
You're serious.
12 hecapates.
I'm going to start building
as soon as the war is over.
We'll have a place
that we can...
visit anytime we want.
Sounds good to me.
Maybe someday, I'll retire here.
Oh, I could see you now...
sitting in your rocking chair
watching the sun set over
the mountains every night...
wondering where you put
your teeth.
Just like
my great-great-grandfather--
in the glass next to the chair.
( laughing )
( sighing )
It's funny how things
turn out, isn't it?
What do you mean?
Did you ever think
that you would become
so attached to Bajor
that you'd want to spend
the rest of your life there?
Hmm.
It wasn't...
part of the master plan
if that's what you mean.
But from the moment
I set foot on this station
nothing has turned out
the way I imagined it.
This was supposed to be
just a temporary assignment
but it's become
much more than that.
I guess I was meant
to come here.
You see, it's
almost like my... my...
Destiny.
Destiny, yes.
I guess when your mother
turns out to be part Prophet
or part wormhole alien
or whatever it is
you want to call her...
words like "destiny"
begin to mean something.
When I look at the picture
of this woman with my father
I think to myself,
"Yes, that's Sarah, my mother."
But she's not just a woman--
she's more than that.
And when I look at myself
in the mirror...
You don't just see a man--
you see more than that.
Does that bother you?
Do I act like
it bothers me?
You're not answering
my question.
I guess when you first
told me about Sarah
I was a little surprised.
More than a little.
All right, I was
very surprised.
But... the more
I thought about it
the more I realized what
an amazing thing it was...
is.
I'm glad you think so.
I do.
And...
part-Prophet or not...
you're still
my Benjamin
and I love you.
I bumped into Captain Boday
the other night.
Captain Boday?
The Gallamite.
Jadzia dated him.
Oh! The toothy smile and
the transparent skull?
That's him.
What's he doing
on the station?
The Gallamites are supplying
duranium for the war effort.
Personally, I don't know what
Jadzia ever saw in the man.
Well, his brains.
( chuckling )
Did he know who you were?
Not at first.
But when he
found out
I bet he laid on the charm.
You could say that.
Ah, the man's insufferable.
He's opinionated
and arrogant...
And charming.
BASHIR:
If you say so.
Something wrong?
We just got word
from the Klingons.
The Rotarran and the Koraga
were ambushed
by a Dominion patrol
near the Badlands.
Worf was commanding
the Koraga.
It didn't make it.
The Rotarran recovered
six escape pods.
Worf wasn't aboard any of them.
Heard anything
from the Defiant?
I talked to Benjamin
this morning.
He said that, according
to the Koraga's crew
Worf was the last one
to leave the Bridge.
No one knows if he made it
to the escape pod.
My money says he did.
We haven't seen the last
of that crazy Klingon.
They've been searching
for three days.
They'll find him.
It's just going
to take a while.
You know what it's
like in the Badlands.
There's a lot of
sensor interference.
I should have gone
with them.
And what would you be able
to do that they can't?
Probably nothing,
but it would be easier
than just sitting here,
waiting.
He'll be back
before you know it.
You really think so?
Absolutely.
The night before
he went on patrol
he brought the Koraga's
crew in here
and bought them three
barrels of bloodwine.
And...?
And he didn't
pay the tab.
Do you really think
he'd go to Sto-Vo-Kor
owing me money?
He doesn't even like you.
Exactly!
He couldn't enjoy
the afterlife
knowing I had
something on him.
( chuckling )
Thanks, Quark.
Ops to Lieutenant Dax.
Go ahead.
You have an incoming
transmission from the Defiant.
Patch it through.
What is it, Benjamin?
I'm afraid we're going to have
to call off the search.
You're giving up?
We don't have any choice.
There are
a dozen Jem'Hadar ships
closing on our position.
But what if he's still
out there somewhere?
Let's face it--
the odds aren't good.
We don't even know
if he made it off the Koraga.
I'm sorry.
DAMAR:
The Defiant is returning
to Federation space.
I'm ordering our
ships to pursue.
No. Divert them to the Son'a
outpost on Devos II.
Why?
We need their help
to protect the new
ketracel-white facility.
The Federation...
has been made aware
of its location.
Can't the Son'a
protect it?
Are you questioning
my orders?
That would be... foolish.
I wonder what...
the Defiant
was doing out there.
Looking for survivors
from the Koraga.
For that long?
Our adversaries
don't view
their soldiers
as expendable.
They're not bred
in hatcheries
like the Jem'Hadar.
If you have something to say,
Damar, say it.
Do you have any idea
the casualties
Cardassia has taken?
There's not one family that
hasn't lost someone in this war.
Their sacrifices
won't be in vain.
We will be victorious.
A bit early, isn't it--
even for you?
Just something
to warm the bones.
It's freezing in here.
The Founder prefers it that way.
I don't see
why we should suffer.
She hasn't been in here
for days.
Feel free to dress warmly.
I wonder what she does
in her quarters all day.
She didn't look well
the last time I saw her.
I hope she's not ill.
How can a God be ill?
Maybe she's not a God.
Whether you believe the Founders
are Gods or not is irrelevant.
All they require from you
is obedience.
Now, the Founder wants
a subspace com link
installed in her quarters.
I'll see to it.
A secure channel--
separately encoded
and isolated
from the main
communication array.
Why all the secrecy?
Who's she going
to be talking to?
That doesn't concern you.
No, of course it doesn't.
Computer,
override locking mechanism.
COMPUTER:
Authorization.
Authorization: Dax-nine-
seven-four-alpha-three.
Confirmed.
WORF:
This bat'leth belonged
to my father.
I would like you
to have it, Jadzia.
( baby crying )
Go, I will take care of Yoshi.
JADZIA:
Worf, that's very sweet,
but let's face it--
you're not good with babies.
WORF:
I am a Klingon warrior.
I have stood in battle
against Kelvans twice my size.
I courted and won the heart
of the magnificent Jadzia Dax.
If I can do these things
I can make this child
go to sleep.
You come first, before career,
before duty, before anything.
JADZIA:
I love you.
WORF:
And I love you.
JADZIA:
Worf, we may never
see each other again
but before you leave,
I want you to know
that the answer is "yes."
WORF:
Yes. Yes to what?
JADZIA:
Yes, I will marry you.
WORF:
You must go to Sirella
and beg her forgiveness.
JADZIA:
I don't beg.
SIRELLA:
Jadzia, daughter of Kela
does your heart beat
only for this man?
JADZIA:
Yes.
SIRELLA:
And do you swear
to join with him
and stand with him against
all who would oppose you?
JADZIA: ( softly ):
I swear.
SIRELLA:
And do you swear
to join with him
and stand with him against
all who would oppose you?
I swear.
Colonel.
Captain, we
have a problem.
It's Ezri.
She's gone.
Gone?
There's a runabout missing.
She must have gotten
it into her head
to go looking for Worf.
What could she
be thinking?
She's a Dax.
Sometimes they don't think...
they just do.
( shaky breathing )
I'm not spacesick.
I'm not...
( com beep )
Uh-oh.
Sisko to Ganda.
Ganda, respond.
Ganda here.
( imitating static )
I'm not reading you very well.
There's... ( imitating static)
interference.
Dax, turn that ship
around and get back here.
What was that, Benjamin?
( Dax imitating static )
Cut it out, old man.
I'm not buying it.
( Dax imitating static )
I gave you an
order, Lieutenant.
Don't worry, sir.
I'll find him.
We can send the Defiant
to bring her back.
No.
Let her go.
Captain?
Send her a copy of the
Defiant's sensor logs.
There's no sense in her
searching the area we did.
Aye, sir.
Sir, do you think
there's any chance
she'll be able
to find him?
I wish I could say yes.
Then, may I ask why you're
letting her do this?
Because she needs to...
and because she'd
never forgive me
if I stopped her.
Computer, show me
the position of the Koraga
at the time it was attacked.
( beeping )
Which escape pods
were recovered?
The six starboard pods
were recovered.
Why none from the port side?
Unknown.
Assuming someone made it
to the port escape pod
closest to the Bridge
calculate its trajectory.
Computer, take us
to the coordinates
where it would've entered
the Badlands.
Acknowledged.
Computer...
cut all engines.
Warning: Without
maneuvering thrusters
the ship may be swept into areas
of plasma-flare activity.
I know, but with any luck,
the currents will take us
to the same place
they took Worf.
Cut the engines.
( engines powering down )
( shaky breathing )
Ben...
Hmm?
What are you
doing up?
I couldn't sleep.
Oh, it's coming along.
Well, I thought
if I did some work
it would take my mind
off things.
If Worf is out there,
she'll find him.
Hmm.
So, what do you think?
It's going to
be beautiful.
These windows face south
towards the valley.
Be a nice view.
Did you know
there's a running stream
on the property?
And the soil is perfect
for growing kava.
I could make
my own spring wine.
The Emissary's
special reserve--
it'll be a big seller.
Hmm.
I can't decide
whether I should
open up this wall
or keep
the kitchen separate.
No, open it up.
Who wants to be
locked away cooking
when you've got
guests over?
Well, a man needs
to concentrate in the kitchen.
I mean, you can't have
people coming in
and sticking their fingers
in your pots.
It's your house.
I want it to be our house.
Let's get married.
Do you mean it?
I love you.
Oh...
Well, does that mean "yes"?
( laughs )
What do you think?
If you're going
to play hard to get...
Aha.
What a beautiful ring.
Kasidy Yates...
will you marry me?
Yes.
Yes, Mr. Sisko...
I will.
( woozy groaning )
Warning: plasma-flow
activity ahead.
( alarm blaring )
You're not kidding.
Re-establishing engine control
is recommended.
No.
Let's sit tight.
Our only hope
of finding that escape pod
is to follow the currents.
( sighs )
Transfer all available power
to the shields.
Acknowledged.
( gasping )
Computer, hold position.
Activate a tractor beam
and lock on to that pod.
Worf.
Ezri.
You're hurt.
It is nothing.
( exhausted sigh )
You are alone.
The Defiant was forced
to call off its search
because of the Jem'Hadar.
Why would Captain Sisko risk
sending a runabout
to look for me?
He didn't.
I came without his permission.
You're a fellow officer.
I would've done the same
for Kira or Julian.
Of course.
I will do it myself.
I'll contact the station
and tell them
we're on our way back.
Founder...
it is an honor
to be summoned
to your presence.
I trust the new
communications system
meets your needs.
It's adequate.
I'm glad.
If I can be of any
further assistance...
When the time comes.
The vaccine--
how is it progressing?
I regret that it failed
to stabilize
the latest sample you provided.
I see.
I have a team
of Vorta doctors
working night and
day to find a cure.
Have them document their efforts
and then eliminate them.
Founder?
Activate their clones
and order them to continue
their predecessors' work.
Perhaps a fresh perspective
will speed matters along.
Of course.
The Cardassians--
what have you told them?
They know nothing.
Good.
The sickness that has
infected the Great Link
is none of their concern.
They may be our allies,
but they are not to be trusted.
We must not show weakness.
This unfortunate malady
will soon be behind us.
I won't rest
until a cure is found.
See that you don't.
We'll require... another sample.
Very well.
You may go now.
So you approve?
Approve?
I'm the one who set you up
with Kasidy in
the first place.
Yes, so you did.
Practically had
to twist your arm.
"A freighter captain?
You want me to go out
with a freighter captain?"
Yeah, well, you have to admit
that the job description
conjures up a certain image.
Yeah. You shouldn't
have doubted me.
I knew from the first time
I met her that she
was the woman for you.
If you're going
to take credit,
you are also going to have
to take on responsibilities.
Like what?
Like being my best man.
Are you serious?
Absolutely.
I mean, are, are you sure
you don't want to ask
Grandpa or Dax?
No, no.
So what do you say?
I'm honored.
( laughs softly )
Best man, huh?
Yes.
Yeah... that means
I get to plan the
bachelor party.
( chuckling )
( console beeping )
What are you doing?
I am realigning
the inertial stabilizers.
But didn't you just do that
a few hours ago?
I want to make sure
the systems are running
at optimal efficiency.
Right.
( sighs )
So... what was it like
being in that escape pod
for so long?
Quiet.
What did you do
to spend the time?
Nothing.
Nothing?
I bet the acoustics in there
were pretty good.
What did you sing?
Klingon opera?
I did not sing.
Which one?
Shevok'tah gish?
No.
Gav'ot toH'va.
Ambitious.
Those solos
are for a tenor.
As you said...
the acoustics
were favorable.
I remember the first night
that you played that for Jadzia.
I'm sorry.
No need to apologize.
Though I would prefer
we not discuss her.
I understand.
( sighs )
What about Alexander?
What about him?
Is it all right if I ask
about the son of Worf?
I hear he's been made
weapons officer of the Ya'Vang.
They were shorthanded.
You make it sound
like he didn't deserve it.
That was not my intention.
Are you ever going
to ease up on him?
My relationship with Alexander
is not your concern.
Oh, that's funny,
because on our wedding night
you told me that...
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have mentioned
our wedding night...
I mean, Jadzia's wedding night.
( sighs )
This is ridiculous.
We can't have a conversation
if you refuse
to talk about the things
that we have in common.
Then perhaps we should not
have a conversation.
You have been avoiding me
for the past six months now.
I did not ask you
to come aboard the station.
And I would have left,
but you told me to stay.
And I am beginning
to regret it.
( scoffs )
If it wasn't for me,
you'd still be drifting around
in an escape pod
singing Klingon opera.
( console beeping )
( alarm blaring )
Sensors are
detecting two ships
closing on our position.
They're Jem'Hadar fighters.
I'm dropping out of warp.
Is that a good idea?
We cannot outrun them.
The Goralis
system is nearby.
We might be able
to lose them there.
They're coming in behind us.
Transfer auxiliary
power to aft shields.
Shields are down to 30 percent.
I am taking us
into the atmosphere.
Their ships are not designed
for sub-orbital flight.
They are pulling away.
Glad to hear it,
but that last hit
took out
our starboard thrusters.
We are losing altitude.
I can't compensate.
( alarm blaring )
We must abandon ship.
( alarm continues )
Energize.
That was a good call.
We may be here
several days.
I will reconnoiter the area.
Set up a com link and try
to contact the station.
Right.
Where's the com unit?
You didn't take one?
I thought you did.
( sighing ):
No.
Now we have no way of
contacting the station.
Thanks for spelling
it out for me.
( frustrated sigh )
Look on the bright side.
We'll have plenty
of time to talk.
( laughing )
No, I-I-I know.
What do you say
we have Bill Ross
perform the ceremony?
My mother would prefer
her daughter
to be married by a minister
but an Admiral
is the next best thing.
That's good.
I'll talk to him.
About the guest list--
I wanted to keep it small,
just family and friends.
Well, that's fine by me.
There's only room
for 30 or 40 people
in the Wardroom.
That just leaves the menu.
Do you mind if I ask Quark
to do the catering?
Just make sure
he doesn't overcharge us.
I'll make sure
I can cut a deal.
Kasidy, what else do
we need to talk about?
I have the feeling we're
forgetting something.
You tell me.
You're the one
who's been married before.
Well, that's just it.
It was a lot more
complicated before.
People get carried
away with weddings.
I... just want it
to be nice and simple.
Excuse me, Emissary.
Hello, Sahgi.
I wanted
to congratulate you--
both of you.
Oh, aren't you sweet.
Thank you.
Um, who told you
we were getting married?
Everybody's talking about it.
Can I be one
of your dais bearers?
My what, honey?
For the bridal procession.
I know you
can only choose 51 girls
but it would be
such an honor for me.
Well, um...
People are saying
it's going to be
the biggest wedding
Bajor's ever seen.
They are?
The Emissary's getting married.
( excited voices approaching)
Ben?
Kasidy... I think
this is going to be
a little more complicated
than we thought.
( excited murmuring )
What I wouldn't give
to wipe the smirk off
that little Vorta's face.
Still... power does have
its privileges.
Dukat.
Leave us.
Does Weyoun
know you're here?
Ah, I see he still
has you under his thumb.
My concern is for you.
The last time you saw him,
you made certain promises--
promises you weren't
able to keep.
I may have failed
to reopen the wormhole
but I assure you,
I have no regrets.
You see, I've come to know
the love of the Pah-wraiths.
You almost sound
as if you believe it.
I do.
What brings you here?
I've come to see you,
old friend.
I need your help.
I'm afraid you have
an exaggerated sense
of my importance.
Damar...
But I'll do what I can.
I knew you would.
( leaves rustling )
( grunting )
Dinner.
Why'd you have to kill
a defenseless animal?
We have plenty of field rations.
I've been eating field
rations for six days.
I am sick of field rations.
So you traipsed into the jungle
and phasered yourself
something to eat?
I did not use a phaser.
I used this.
Oh. Well, that makes it
all the more sporting.
It took me hours
to track this animal
and while doing so,
I could have easily
been attacked by
a predator myself.
Oh, spare me
the "one with nature" speech.
I killed it, and now
I am going to eat it.
If you do not want any
then have some
more field rations.
Fine.
Jadzia would
have understood.
Oh, I thought we weren't
supposed to talk about her.
I was merely making
an observation.
Have you been able to
boost the combadge signal?
Not enough to get a message
back to the station.
I'll bet Jadzia
would have been able to do it.
I was merely making
an observation.
Perhaps we should both refrain
from making observations.
You're right.
Let's just go about
our own business
and exchange
as few words as possible.
What is it about men?
They either don't talk
at all-- like you--
or they talk too much--
like Boday.
Boday?
The Gallamite?
We had dinner on the station
before I left.
I see.
If he talks so much
why did you have
dinner with him?
He's interesting
and he has
a good sense of humor.
Tell me...
did Jadzia...?
she and Boday, uh...?
I don't have to answer
that question.
She did.
( sighs )
Worf, she didn't
even know you back then.
I do not wish
to hear your excuses.
My excuses?
I'm not the one
who slept with him.
You had dinner with him.
Who are you angry with--
me or Jadzia?
Both.
You know what?
You're crazy.
You could make
anyone crazy.
Don't turn your back.
Talk to me, you coward.
Do not call me a coward.
( frustrated grunt )
I can't believe
I'm stuck here with you.
Perhaps you would rather
be back on the station
with Captain Boday
you sli'vak!
( leaves rustling )
( footsteps approaching )
( groaning )
Ezri...
Where are we?
I am not certain.
( grunting )
Why would the Breen
take us prisoner?
We are not at war with them.
And what were they
doing on Goralis?
That's a long way
from Breen space.
Ow.
You must have gotten hurt
when they stunned us.
Actually, I think it
happened last night.
You do not regret what happened
last night, do you?
Why do you say that?
Jadzia explained to me
that joined Trill
are not supposed to become...
involved... with anyone
they were intimate with
in a previous life.
I bet you've broken a few
Klingon rules in your time.
( engines rumbling )
What's that?
We must be on a Breen ship.
The Federation
has pulled the Sixth Fleet
from the Bolian front.
What do you suppose
they're planning?
Damar.
Yes?
What's wrong with you?
You're distracted.
Am I?
You've been pacing
back and forth all morning.
Just trying
to stay warm.
CARDASSIAN:
Legate Damar.
Please report
to your quarters.
Acknowledged.
Excuse me.
If you think I don't know
what you're up to
you're a bigger fool than Dukat.
Dukat?
He used to entertain
lady friends, as well.
Guilty as charged.
That surgeon you recommended
does excellent work.
What do you think?
Let's hope she does as well
when it comes time
to reverse the procedure.
( laughing )
Believe me, Damar,
I have no desire
to remain a Bajoran
the rest of my life
but for now,
I'm afraid it's necessary.
SISKO:
Personal Log, Stardate 52576.2.
Dax and Worf
are four days overdue.
Dominion activity
at their last known position
has prevented us
from sending a search team.
For the time being,
there's nothing to do but wait
and hope
that they're all right.
Why have you brought me here?
( heartbeat thumping )
Show yourselves.
You are the Sisko.
Sarah?
You must accept your destiny.
Your path is
a difficult one.
She cannot share it
with you.
Are you talking
about Kasidy?
She cannot walk
the same path.
You don't understand.
I love her.
We're going to be married.
That is not your destiny.
My destiny is my own.
I'm a man.
I have the right
to live my life
without your
interference.
I gave you life.
Sarah Sisko was
my mother, not you.
I shared her existence,
guided her to your father
so that you would be born.
You must walk the path alone.
You're not listening to me.
I want to spend
my life with her.
If you do, you will know
nothing but sorrow.
You don't care how I feel.
All that matters to you
is that I do what you want.
You are the Sisko.
You are part of me.
If that's true, if you
really do care about me
if you do consider
me your son
then let me have this.
It is not for you to have.
There are still
many tasks ahead of you.
Accept your fate.
Your greatest trial
is about to begin.
Don't be afraid.
All will be...
as it should be.
Mother...
Stay on the path, Benjamin.