Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
The Rotarran and the Koraga
were ambushed
by a Dominion patrol
near the Badlands.
Worf was commanding
the Koraga.
It didn't make it.
Let's get married.
Do you mean it?
I love you.
Does Weyoun know
you're here?
Ah, I see he still has
you under his thumb.
We have a problem.
It's Ezri... there's
a runabout missing.
She must have gotten
it into her head
to go looking for Worf.
They're coming in behind us.
The vaccine...
how is it progressing?
I regret
that it failed to stabilize
the latest sample you provided.
I can't believe
I'm stuck here with you.
Perhaps you would
rather be back on the station
with Captain Boday.
That surgeon
you recommended
does excellent work.
Your path is a difficult one.
She cannot share it with you.
I want to spend
my life with her.
If you do, you will know
nothing but sorrow.
And now, the continuation.
Did they tell you
why you can't marry Kasidy?
The Prophets didn't
say that I can't.
They just said that I shouldn't.
It-it's the same thing.
I-I don't see
why it's any of their business.
Everything I do
is their business.
Have you told Kasidy?
No, she's on a cargo run.
She won't be back
for a couple of days.
And when she gets back
what are you
going to tell her?
That some Prophet who said
that she's your mother, Sarah
told you not to marry her?
Jake, you're not making me
feel any better.
Captain Sisko,
Kai Winn is here to see you.
Send her in.
Talk later.
Emissary, congratulations.
Eminence.
I'm so happy for you.
This wedding is
a momentous event for Bajor.
I want to make sure
the proceedings
reflect its importance
so I've come to assist
in the preparations.
Hmm.
That's very kind of you
but I'm not sure
that it's necessary.
Well, you don't
have to thank me.
I'm glad to do it.
I understand that
you've asked
Vedek Telna to perform
the ceremony.
Perhaps you thought
I would be unavailable
but since I'm here,
I think you'll agree
it would be more
appropriate for me
to do it.
I'll talk to Vedek Telna
and I'm sure he'd be
willing to step aside.
Well, these
are joyful days indeed.
You've given the Prophets
reason to smile.
Is there something wrong,
Emissary?
You seem troubled.
The Prophets
came to me in a vision.
I see.
They warned me
that I was going to have
to face a great trial.
Did they say what it would be?
I'm afraid not.
The Prophets don't always
make themselves clear.
Well, I wouldn't know
as they've never spoken
to me directly.
In any case
you have always been willing
to do whatever it is they ask.
Well... I pray that
they'll give you
the strength to
face your trial.
I sense you're
going to need it.
Emissary.
Eminence.
May I show you
to your quarters?
Well, thank you, my child.
Her pagh is strong.
Solbor?
She will serve us well.
Prophets...
I have waited so long
for you to speak to me.
How can I serve you?
The Sisko has faulted.
You must bring the Restoration.
The Restoration?
Bajor's fate rests with you.
Tell me what to do.
The Guide will reveal the way.
What Guide?
He will come to you.
How will I know him?
He will have the wisdom
of the land.
Of the land?
I don't understand.
Only you can bring
the Restoration.
Bajor's fate rests with you.
Eminence...
are you all right?
What happened?
The Prophets...
they spoke to me.
They will be feeding us soon.
If we could position ourselves
on both sides of the door
we might be able to disarm
the first Breen
that comes through.
Worf.
Face it.
The "Guard, my cellmate
is ill" trick didn't work.
Neither did your
"I'll make a tool
and short-circuit the door"
idea.
We must not give up.
The first duty of every captured
officer is to attempt escape.
What's the special today?
Algae paste, my favorite.
I wonder what the Breen
look like under those helmets.
They say no one
has ever seen one
and lived to speak of it.
Maybe they're all furry.
It's supposed to be
very cold on Breen.
Well, one thing
is certain...
They're horrible cooks?
They are dangerous.
They do not tolerate
incursions into their space.
During the Second Empire
Chancellor Mow'ga sent
a fleet of Klingon ships
to conquer their homeworld
and they were never
heard from again.
We have been traveling
for three days.
We could be in
Breen space by now.
Well, I wouldn't
rule out the possibility
that they saw
our shuttle crash
and decided to take us back
to Deep Space 9.
You are being humorous.
Not very, I guess.
Jadzia also used humor
to lift her spirits.
You didn't laugh very much
at her jokes, either.
You are a lot like her.
In some ways.
I thought
that I had lost her forever
but you and I will have
many years together.
Damar.
Damar!
What are you doing here?
Since you're ignoring
your com system
I decided to wake you myself.
I worked late last night.
Yes...
I can see that.
Get yourself cleaned up.
We're leaving this afternoon.
Where are we going?
You needn't concern
yourself with that.
Why didn't you
tell me that before?
I have things to tend to.
You mean your
business with Dukat?
Did you really think
I didn't know he was here?
Masquerading as a Bajoran.
What's he up to this time?
He wouldn't say.
Yet, you helped him
all the same.
Such loyalty.
It would be impressive
if it wasn't so misplaced.
Have you arranged
my transportation?
And your identity documents.
Good. I knew I could
count on you.
You don't look well.
I'm fine.
What happened to that brave
officer I served with?
The one who stood at my side
while we fought
the entire Klingon Empire
with a single ship?
Those were simpler times.
Those days might be gone
but the man
I served with isn't.
He's still within you.
Reach in and grab
hold of him, Damar.
Cardassia needs a leader.
You were its leader once.
You could be again.
Mm-mm. The Pah-wraiths
have shown me
that I have
a different destiny.
Good luck, old friend.
And to you.
The Bajorans believe
it's good luck
for a bride to wear
a Navatan shawl.
What's the matter?
You don't like it.
It's lovely.
Then why the long face?
We need to talk.
Why do I have a feeling
I'm not going to like this?
There's something
I haven't told you.
A few days ago
one of the Prophets
came to me in a vision.
It was Sarah.
Your mother?
What did she want?
She said the path
that I was meant to walk...
is for me alone.
That you can't
walk it with me.
Why?
She said I would
know nothing but sorrow
if I ignored her warning.
Well, that almost
sounds like a threat.
No.
It wasn't anything like that.
She was worried for me.
Like a mother would be.
What are you going to do?
Kasidy, the Prophets
see things that we can't.
If she was that concerned
it must be for a good reason.
You're not answering
my question.
Kasidy...
I love you...
and I want to be with you.
Then be with me, Ben.
I can't.
I can't go against the Prophets.
Kasidy, please.
Try and understand.
No!
Ezri!
It is all right.
You were having
a bad dream.
Where are we?
We're still aboard
the Breen ship.
They were chasing me...
in an ice cave.
It was so cold,
I could barely breathe.
Shh! It is over now.
I couldn't
get away from them.
Every time I looked back,
they were right behind me
and then one of them
grabbed me with this huge claw.
The Breen do
not have claws.
How do you know?
Besides, it-it was a dream.
Dreams are full of things
that don't make sense.
That is why
it is best to ignore them.
How can you say that?
Dreams contain
valuable insights.
Things that don't seem
to make any sense
are actually the key
to what your unconscious
is trying to tell you.
Anyway, I got away from him...
but then,
there was nowhere to run
and then, just when I thought
he was about to kill me
he reached up
and took off his helmet...
And?
And...
it was Julian.
Dr. Bashir.
Isn't that strange?
I wonder what it meant?
Dr. Bashir is a Breen.
Very funny.
Now, the cave could
symbolize the womb.
Maybe my subconscious
is trying to tell me
that I need
to confront emotions
that I've repressed
since birth.
But which one?
I've been born nine times.
This is ridiculous.
I'm a Counselor.
Analyzing dreams
is part of my job.
Jadzia never talked
about her dreams.
Well, I'm not Jadzia, am I?
Worf!
Where are you taking him?
...have mercy upon
your humble supplicant
and make me worthy
of your great task.
Grant me the strength
not to fail you.
Eminence?
Yes?
There is a man here
who requests an
audience with you.
Show him in.
This is Anjohl Tennan
from Relliketh.
Welcome, my son.
Thank you for
seeing me, Eminence.
How can I help you?
I've come to ask your blessing
so that I may have prosperity
in the coming season.
What is it you do?
Oh, I'm just a simple man
of the land.
Of the land?
I'm a farmer.
I grow moba and...
Your pagh is strong, Anjohl.
I've been waiting for you.
Oh, here, let me help you.
It's not right that a Ranjen
should be serving
a common farmer.
Please sit.
You're our guest.
If I told my neighbors
I was having tea with the Kai
they'd never believe me.
Thank you, Solbor.
Thank you.
Tell me about
yourself, Anjohl.
You came here to
pray for prosperity.
Have things been
difficult for you?
Yes.
Rogath blight destroyed
my entire crop last year.
Oh, I'm sorry
to hear that.
Most of the farms
in Relliketh
fell victim to it.
"And the land shall be
poisoned by a great evil."
It's from the Ancient Texts...
Talnot's Prophesy
of the Final Days.
I see.
Well...
tell me more about this blight.
Unfortunately,
the only way to eradicate it
is to burn your fields
at the first sign
of contamination.
Go on.
Then you must let
your land lie fallow
for a whole season
to allow
for the restoration
of the soil.
Restoration...
The following year
the fields will be
fertile again.
"The poison must be purged away
so the land can be reborn."
Eminence?
Do you pray to the
Prophets, Anjohl?
Oh, every day.
And have they
ever answered you?
In a vision or
in your dreams?
Oh, there have been times
when I thought
I could feel their presence.
But spoken to me? No.
Surely, they'd reserve
such a blessing
for someone like you.
Well, you are right.
They have spoken to me
and they told me they were going
to send you here.
Me?
You've been
blessed, Anjohl.
They've anointed you
to be my Guide.
I don't understand.
You are going to help me
bring about the Restoration
of Bajor.
But surely the Prophets
would have chosen
someone more worthy than I.
You must have more faith
in yourself, Anjohl
and in the Prophets.
Of course.
And rest assured,
they'll reveal
what they want from us
and together, we will walk
the path they've laid out.
Ah, the bottom line is
the Chief won't be able
to get to it
for a few days.
Not good enough.
I told General Martok
his ships would be repaired
by tomorrow.
We have engineering crews
working 26 hours a day.
We're doing the best we can.
I-I know you are.
It's just that things are...
a little complicated for me now.
I can imagine.
Nerys...
the Prophets came to me...
and told me that...
Kasidy and I...
are not meant
to walk the same path.
Ah.
I see.
Well, that explains that.
I'm sorry
but the Prophets
wouldn't ask you
to do something like that
without a reason.
You would think
they would tell me what it is.
It doesn't work like that,
and you know that.
Well, what they're asking
you to do isn't easy
but they've never led you
down the wrong path.
Not so far.
There's always a first time.
To them, I'm "the Sisko"
an instrument
to carry out their wishes
but they forget
that I am also human
with dreams and wishes
of my own.
They say that marrying
Kasidy is a mistake.
Maybe it is,
but it's my mistake to make.
I wouldn't go
against the Prophets.
You're doing
the right thing.
Founder.
When do we reach
the rendezvous coordinates?
Approximately
36 hours.
May I say
your plan is brilliant?
I'm confident that it will
turn the war in our favor.
Let's hope
that you're right.
Founder?
About Damar... I trust
he won't be a problem.
I'm sure he'll
have his concerns
but you needn't
worry about that.
I'll deal with him
when the time comes.
See that you do.
I find him most trying.
I'll have
the temperature lowered.
You'll be more comfortable.
Fight them!
Sto-Vo-Kor!
Worf!
No! No!
I will not dishonor
her memory!
What have they done to you?
Alexander!
Worf... wake up, please.
Ezri...
Where did they take you?
An interrogation chamber.
They used some sort of...
cortical implant
to probe my memory.
I wonder what they were
trying to find out.
I do not know.
I lost consciousness.
That's probably a good thing.
I should have tried harder
to resist them.
Careful.
These Breen are without honor.
Worf, sit down please.
Have something to eat.
This is intolerable!
They have us caged
up like animals.
Stop it.
A Klingon would rather
die than be held captive.
What are you going to do?
Kill yourself
and leave me here alone?
This is no time
for your jokes!
It's no time for Klingon
chest-thumping either.
Stop it!
More spring wine?
Yes.
It's extraordinary.
I've never tasted
anything like this.
Well, it's a rare vintage
from before the occupation.
I was going to
give this bottle
to the Emissary
as a wedding gift.
Well, I'm honored
that you would choose
to share it with me.
Well, I doubt that he
would have been able
to appreciate it as much,
not being a Bajoran.
I suppose not.
The Prophets may have chosen
to speak through him, but...
he's not really one of us,
is he?
No. No, he isn't.
There are times...
when I wonder if he truly
understands our people.
Still, it's not
for me to question
why the Prophets chose
him as their Emissary.
You forget the Prophets
chose you as my Guide.
You must speak
your mind freely, Anjohl.
The Emissary didn't suffer
through the occupation.
He has no idea what the
Cardassians did to us.
Those years left many scars
on Bajor's soul.
So... how can he help heal...
what he could never comprehend?
I have often asked myself
the same question.
I survived the occupation
purely by chance.
Tell me.
When the resistance destroyed
the Cardassian outpost
in Relliketh
Gul Dukat ordered 100 Bajorans
rounded up.
His intention was to
send us to the capital
for public execution.
100 from Relliketh?
Mm.
When did that occur?
Just before the Great Famine.
By sheer luck
my transport was rerouted
to a labor camp
and I learned years later
that the dispatcher
had misread the orders.
Well, his name was Prenar
and he didn't
misread the orders.
How could you know that?
I was a Ranjen at that time.
I convinced the Vedek
who led my Order
that we needed to take a more
active role in the resistance.
He allowed me to remove
some gemstones
from our tabernacle.
I used those
to bribe various
Cardassians in exchange
for some small acts of leniency.
Prenar was one of them.
I paid him to reroute
the transport from Relliketh.
You saved my life.
Even then...
our fates were linked.
Yes.
Uh, sorry to interrupt,
but I have something for you.
The, uh...
the item that you ordered.
Terellian diamonds aren't
that easy to come by
especially with this war on.
Needless to say,
it was non-refundable.
Thank you, Quark.
Um...
seems a shame to let
something so beautiful
go to waste.
I'm going to help you
through this, Garak.
I'm not just saying this
because I'm your sister.
You have a gift.
No more algae paste.
I'm not like you.
I'm not like you, Joran.
I'm not a murderer.
Shh.
It's all right.
I was your wife.
Why don't you talk to me?
I love you.
Kiss me.
Kiss me, Julian.
Yes?
Forgive me for disturbing you
at this hour, Eminence
but Anjohl is here,
and he insists on seeing you.
I'll be right there.
Eminence
I hope I didn't
wake you.
That's all right.
You may go, Solbor.
As you wish.
Something wondrous
has happened.
I talked to my brother
in Relliketh.
He told me that
this morning
when he went out to
inspect the fields
he found moba saplings
sprouting from the soil.
But it's impossible.
We only planted last week.
Tell me...
could it be a sign?
Yes, it is a sign...
a sign from the Prophets.
They're telling you
that your farm
will thrive
under your brother's care.
They don't want you
to go back to Relliketh.
They want you at my side.
Then this is where
I'll stay, Eminence.
Adami.
What a beautiful name.
It's all right.
The Prophets brought
us together.
That's the last of it.
Tell Kilby to start the
final departure check.
Yes, ma'am.
I made a mistake.
I don't care what
the Prophets want.
I want to marry you.
We'll worry
about the rest later.
Ben, don't do this to me...
not if you're going
to change your mind again.
I won't.
I love you.
Okay, let's go.
Where?
Where do you think?
Didn't think
you were going to make it.
I only heard about
it 20 minutes ago.
Me, too, and I'm the caterer.
Thank you, Quark.
I can't work
under these conditions.
Too bad Ezri and Worf
couldn't be here.
Well, they probably
got held up
picking out a wedding gift.
Something for you, Nog?
Usually when we come
to events like this
you're the one who
has to remind me
to smile.
I wonder why they decided
not to have a Bajoran ceremony.
I hope the Prophets
forgive them.
So do I.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
Well done, Nog.
Considering I only had
a few minutes to practice.
One of the most pleasant duties
of a senior officer
is the privilege of joining
two people together
in matrimony.
Today, I have the honor
to unite Kasidy Danielle Yates
and Benjamin Lafayette Sisko
in marriage.
Kasidy, do you accept this man
as your husband
to love and cherish
above all others
until death separates you?
I do.
Benjamin, do you accept
this woman as your wife
to love and cherish her
above all others
until death separates you?
I do.
These rings
are a symbol of your love
for each other
and a promise to abide
by the vows
you've made today.
With this ring, I thee wed.
With this ring...
This is not meant
to be, Benjamin.
I've made my decision.
Your trial is at hand.
You must be strong.
Kasidy gives me strength.
Why can't you understand that?
If you do this
you will know only sorrow.
You shared
my mother's existence.
You must have some
idea what love is.
You should know that
I will never be happy
without Kasidy.
Your path is a difficult one.
I cannot change...
what is to come.
I know.
Be careful...
my son.
Ben?
With this ring...
I thee wed.
By the power vested in me
by the United Federation
of Planets...
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
I need to talk to you.
Oh?
I demand to know
where we are going.
Of course.
In fact, I was just coming
to your quarters
to discuss the matter.
Were you?
I've kept you in the dark
for too long, Damar
and for that, I apologize.
You are the leader of Cardassia
and you deserve to know
everything we're doing
and I have a feeling
you're going to be very pleased.
Would you stop that?
What's wrong?
You haven't said
a word to me in hours.
I should not have trusted you
with my heart.
What is that supposed to mean?
You dishonor me and yourself.
I must have missed something
when I was gone.
How long have you had
these feelings for him?
For who?
Dr. Bashir.
- What?
- When the Breen
brought you back,
you spoke his name.
I did?
Yes. You said
that you loved him.
Julian?
I said that I loved Julian?
Do not try to deny it.
Oh, Worf.
Look, I admit that I find him
to be... charming...
and obviously, he is an
attractive man, but I'm not...
You are in love with him!
I am not!
Then why do you
dream about him?
You're the one that said
that dreams don't mean anything.
I should've known.
Jadzia had feelings for him
as well.
Would you
stop comparing me to her!
We meet at last.
Gifts?
How thoughtful.
You should be honored.
You're witnessing
an historic moment...
the birth of the alliance
between the Dominion
and the Breen.
Changes everything, doesn't it?