Last time on
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine...
This is intolerable.
They have us caged
up like animals.
Stop it!
We meet at last.
Gifts?
How thoughtful.
You should be honored.
You're witnessing
an historic moment...
the birth of the alliance
between the Dominion
and the Breen.
And now the continuation.
We will secure
the prisoners below.
They will share a cell.
They may wish to...
physically comfort each other
on the long trip back
to Cardassia.
I find interspecies
mating rituals
fascinating to watch.
Interesting device.
Oh, I am so sorry.
Where are my manners?
Allow me to introduce
Legate Damar
leader of the
Cardassian Union.
Thot Gor.
Thot.
That's the equivalent
of a Legate, isn't it?
What did he say?
He says, "You need to have
your universal
translator adjusted."
I would have if I'd known
we were meeting
with the Breen.
It is a distinct pleasure
to finally meet you.
Thank you.
If our face-to-face talks
are as productive
as our subspace
communications
have been, I'm sure we'll
sign the treaty documents
within a few days.
I haven't even seen
this treaty.
We'll discuss it later.
The alliance between
the Breen Confederacy
and the Dominion will end
this destructive war
that has torn this
Quadrant apart.
With the Breen at our side
the Federation will not be able
to stand against us.
They'll be erased
from the face of the galaxy.
This is outrageous.
Have you read this treaty?
Parts of it.
There's a reference
to territorial concessions
that the Cardassians
are to make to the Breen
but it doesn't say what
those concessions are.
Oh, you needn't worry
about that.
It's all been itemized
in a secret protocol
between the Dominion
and the Breen.
All that is required of you
is to sign the document
as the acknowledged leader
of the Cardassian Union.
I want to see this protocol.
Then it wouldn't be much
of a secret then, would it?
You expect me to agree
to territorial concessions
when I haven't even seen
what they are?
Damar, you are missing
the point.
We need the Breen
to win this war.
When it's over
there will be more than enough
territories available
to compensate Cardassia for
the loss of a few minor planets.
There are no minor planets
in the Cardassian Union.
Do you know what I think
you should do?
Talk to Thot Gor.
Express your concerns.
He's very reasonable
and quite personable
when you get to know him.
I don't trust him
or his people.
The Founders should
never have agreed
to give away Cardassian
territory without my consent.
I'm sorry.
I think I misunderstood you.
It sounded
as if you were implying
that Cardassian territory
doesn't belong to the Founders.
Surely, that isn't
what you meant.
No, of course not.
Oh, good.
I look forward to receiving
the signed documents from you
within the hour.
Is there something else?
The Klingons have attacked
Septimus III.
I'm aware of that.
Are you also aware that
they've landed 15 divisions?
The Cardassian troops
will never survive
without reinforcements.
I assure you
the Septimus III situation
will be dealt with.
We will not allow your brave
soldiers to perish in vain.
You have my word.
Septimus III will fall
within the week.
Huh! The Cardassian 11th Order.
It's a reserve unit...
old men and walking wounded.
They don't stand a chance.
I think
you're right.
But enough about the war
with the Dominion.
I want to hear
about the war at home.
You just married that...
freighter captain, didn't you?
Yes.
Then war has broken out,
whether you know it or not...
a long, grueling,
intoxicating war.
I remember the day
my beloved Sirella moved
into my home.
I had a pet targ,
had him since I was a boy...
a filthy, mangy beast
but in his bony breast
beat the heart of a warrior.
Of course,
Sirella loathed him.
Well, to make
a long story short
while she was supervising
the unloading of her bags
Sirella accidentally left
the front door open
and my faithful targ, ever-ready
to follow the call of the wild
tottered outside
on his frail legs
and disappeared
into the forest.
I never laid eyes on him again.
Lady Sirella draws
the first blood.
You see my point.
Don't get me wrong.
I would not trade Sirella
for all the targs on Qo'noS
and, over the course
of our marriage
I've won more than my fair share
of battles between us
but in the end...
I know...
she will win the war.
I'll keep that in mind.
You ate all the milaberries.
Mm. Well, then have
Solbor bring us more.
And give him
another chance
to frown disapprovingly?
The good Ranjen doesn't
much care for me, does he?
You'd think he'd be pleased
to see his Kai so happy.
Are you happy, Adami?
More than I've ever
been in my life.
The Prophets are smiling on us.
Hmm.
They've not only
brought us together
but they've given us
a great task...
the Restoration of Bajor.
Our world will be reborn,
and you will be its leader.
A sacred responsibility.
Yes.
I pray that I'll have
the strength to do
what the Prophets
are asking of me.
I will be at your side.
We won't fail them.
But the Restoration
will not come
without struggle.
There will be those
who will stand in our way.
It is not allowed to interfere
with the will
of the Prophets.
Even those who claim
to speak in their name.
The Emissary.
Mm. In your vision...
the Prophets said
he'd faltered.
I can only hope
that he doesn't choose
to oppose them.
Their love is strong...
but so is their wrath.
I hate to say it
but this is doing wonders
for my back.
I doubt that is what
our captors had in mind.
Probably not.
We must get back
to the station
and warn Starfleet
about the Breen.
You're right.
There's just a few problems.
We're on a Jem'Hadar ship
heading
in the wrong direction
hanging upside down,
and...
And what?
I'm think I'm getting spacesick.
Well, welcome home,
Mrs. Sisko.
Well, thank you, Mr. Sisko.
Mmm.
So, how was your cargo run?
Interesting.
It seems
my Bajoran crew members
have decided that serving
under the wife of the Emissary
is a little different
than serving
under his girlfriend.
I've known some of those people
for ten years or more
and suddenly,
they're asking me for advice
about their children,
their wives, their husbands
their spiritual relationship
with the Prophets.
Welcome to the club.
Which reminds me...
every spring, the Emissary
holds a little ceremony
to bless the women on the
station who want to be mothers.
What does this have
to do with me?
There's been a request made...
several, in fact...
that the new wife
of the Emissary perform
the ceremony this year...
this week, actually.
No.
Kasidy...
No. I've got
to draw the
line somewhere.
I married you,
I didn't convert.
And I'm not going to start...
acting like I suddenly
believe in the Prophets.
I wouldn't want you
to do anything
that you're
uncomfortable with.
Good. Then it's settled.
I'm going to go
take a sonic shower.
Take your time.
Dinner won't be ready
for another 15 minutes.
And so...
the battle begins.
Let me try.
No. You do not have
the necessary strength.
And your fingers
are too fat.
Look out.
Would you just?
Wait. I've got it!
Ow!
Quiet.
Are you hurt?
Yes, I'm hurt.
You just cut my finger
and made me hit my head!
It was an accident.
I still don't see how
getting a pin out of a bunk
is going to
help us escape.
If you would
stop interfering
and allow me
to remove the pin
I would show you.
Let me take a look
at your head.
No, thank you.
The last time you touched me
things got a little
out of control.
You are right about that.
I was seduced and betrayed.
Seduced? I seduced you.
At least we agree on that point.
What?!
You desired
a physical relationship with me
from the very start.
That much was obvious.
You have the biggest ego
of any man I've ever known.
Considering how many men
you have known
that is quite a statement.
Am I supposed to be embarrassed
because Jadzia had a few lovers
before you?
A few?
You're right.
It was more than a few.
It was dozens.
Hundreds. In fact,
I don't think
there's anyone aboard DS9
who wasn't her lover.
Let me take this opportunity
to welcome you both
to Cardassia Prime.
I trust you're being
well-treated so far.
I've been looking over
the information
you supplied to the Breen
during your interrogation
and the results
are a bit confusing
as mental probes so often are.
I was wondering if you wouldn't
mind sifting through the data
and clarifying
certain issues for us.
You can't be serious.
I'm always serious.
You see,
if you don't do as I ask
I'll have to hand you over
to Legate Damar
and you know how ruthless
the Cardassians can be.
"It is my duty to inform you
"that you will be turned over
to a Cardassian Tribunal
where you will be tried
as war criminals."
War criminals?
What are the charges?
That is not necessary
for you to know.
All you need to know
is that you will be
found guilty and executed.
However, if you should
decide to join us
in our search for a quick
end to this miserable war
your sentence
will be reduced
to life imprisonment.
If you want to end the war
why don't you convince
the Founders to surrender?
You know, my dear
it would be such
a shame for you to die
without the good
Dr. Bashir knowing
how you felt about him.
Wait!
Ah, overconfidence...
the hallmark of the Weyouns.
Maybe the Founders
should eliminate that
from your genetic recipe
next time.
They'll just make another copy
of him, you know.
You should have killed me.
There's only one Damar.
I will keep that in mind.
I'm sure you will.
Consider his offer, Klingon.
You die in two days.
Pick that up, and let's go.
There you are.
Who are you?
What do you mean?
I mean, who are you,
Anjohl Tennan?
I want to know everything
about your family,
your childhood...
It would bore you.
Not at all.
What might seem trivial to you
matters a great deal to me.
I need to know more
about this Guide
the Prophets have sent me...
this simple farmer.
Mm.
This man who shares my bed.
We are of Bajor.
We await the Restoration.
I am ready.
I have met the Guide.
You need only
tell me what to do.
I give myself to the Prophets
in all things.
She does not understand.
She is fearful.
There is no other path.
She is the Chosen One.
She must embrace us.
I will.
I swear it.
Give me a chance, please.
Give us your allegiance,
Kai Winn Adami.
Restore us to
our rightful place
in the Celestial Temple.
Reject the false Prophets.
Walk our path
and embrace your own destiny.
Feel our love...
the love...
of the Pah-wraiths.
No!
What is it, Adami?
What's happened?
They... they came to me.
A vision.
Blessed be the Prophets.
No. They weren't the Prophets.
They were...
They were what?
The Pah-wraiths.
Find Solbor.
Tell him to go to the shrine
and bring me the Orb.
I must bare my soul
to the Prophets
and beg their forgiveness.
Eminence, are you
sure that's wise?
What do the Prophets?
Go! Bring me the Orb!
Well, hello.
I'm glad to see
you find the death
of my predecessor
so amusing.
Oh, you misjudge me.
I miss him deeply.
Here. Let's drink to Weyoun 7.
When will the
prisoners be executed?
When the trial is completed.
Legal protocol must be observed.
When?
The execution is scheduled for
tomorrow afternoon, 1400 hours.
Have they agreed to cooperate?
No.
Maybe you should talk
to Worf again.
Ah! Welcome to
our Command Center.
Of course. Go right ahead.
Absolutely not.
That database
is classified.
What Legate Damar
means to say is
that our entire database
is open to you.
Feel free to examine
it at your leisure.
Surely you don't mean that.
On the contrary,
I'm quite sincere.
They don't need
to know everything
about our
military operation
in order to help us.
The decision was made
by the Founder herself.
The Founder has also
decided that, from now on
your military recommendations
will be submitted to Thot Gor
and he will pass it
on to her.
I will not!
I trust
that was simply
an unguarded emotional outburst
so I will ignore it this time.
Make plans to do exactly
as the Founder instructed
or you can schedule an execution
for yourself as well.
Ready.
Leave me!
Oh, shut up!
You never listen.
Look who's talking.
Do you have to do that?
I do it every
day at this time.
I know, but there's
something morbid about it.
Morbid?
That implies that
she's not coming back.
I wasn't implying
anything of the kind.
One of these days,
Ezri's going
to come walking through
those doors again
and this drink is going
to be sitting right here
waiting for her when she does.
Yeah, well
in the meantime,
all you're doing
is reminding us
that she's missing.
No one's forcing you
to sit here.
It was the Badlands.
What?
You said something
about the Badlands.
Oh. Worf.
If his escape pod hadn't
drifted into the Badlands
the Defiant would have picked
him up and Ezri wouldn't
have had to go
looking for him.
Never thought I'd hear
myself saying this
but I wish the Defiant had found
that lumbering Klingon oaf.
Well, we can't do anything
to change what's happened.
We just have to hope
for the best.
Funny, I was just
starting to...
Starting to what?
I don't know.
But there was something...
something about her,
wasn't there?
Something that made
me happy anyway.
She was this old soul
and yet so young at heart
and... and...
I don't know what I'm saying.
Hmm.
Where is he?
He'll be here any moment.
He said there were certain
security precautions
that had to be observed
before the Orb was allowed
to leave
the shrine.
May I ask
what you're planning?
No, you may not.
This is far beyond your ability
to comprehend, Anjohl.
Come in.
The Orb of Prophecy.
Place it on the table and...
and then go.
How may I serve you?
You are not required here.
Thank you.
There's nothing to fear.
Of course not. I'm the Kai.
The Prophets will make
everything clear to me.
Something's wrong.
What?
There's nothing.
The Prophets show me nothing.
They won't speak to me.
They have forsaken me...
...because I have been
in communion with the evil one.
Adami...
I know this may be
hard to hear, but...
you must listen.
I've hidden
something from you.
I didn't come here by chance.
I had a vision.
The true Gods of Bajor
came to me
and asked me to serve them.
The true Gods?
The Pah-wraiths.
They led me to you.
No!
They're not evil.
They care about Bajor.
No!
They want
to make Bajor strong.
Heretic.
Listen to me.
Get away!
Enough!
The Prophets have done
nothing for you.
During the occupation,
they turned their backs
and let our people suffer.
Let me go.
You've sacrificed
everything for them
and how have
they rewarded you?
They've appointed
an alien Emissary.
They've rejected you
at every turn.
Even now,
they won't speak to you.
Solbor!
Shh!
Listen to me, please.
The Pah-wraiths
will give you everything
you've ever dreamt of...
the power...
the adoration of the people.
In spite of your
protestations of humility
that's what you really want;
admit it.
Stop pretending to be
something you're not.
Take what they're offering you.
Get out.
Go.
Crawl back
to your Prophets.
Beg their forgiveness.
Live the rest of your life...
in Sisko's shadow!
I'll do anything you ask.
You need only give the word.
Have you nothing to say to me?
Am I so offensive to your eyes
that I don't exist
for you anymore?
There must be something I can do
to prove to you
that I'm still worthy
of your love.
Go ahead.
This is Kai Winn.
I need to speak with you.
Would you come to my quarters?
Of course.
Colonel Kira to see you,
Eminence.
Come in, my child.
Please sit down.
Thank you
for seeing me
at such a late hour.
What can I do for you?
I have often sensed...
that you don't approve
of how I conduct myself as Kai...
that you believe
I put my own political interests
ahead of the spiritual
well-being of our people.
I wish I could disagree
with that assessment.
I have strayed from the path
the Prophets
have laid down for me.
Eminence...
You don't know.
Eminence.
When you told me
that the Prophets
had spoken to you
I prayed that they
would open your heart
that they would change you.
Oh, I want to change.
I would... I'd do anything
to earn their forgiveness
but I'm afraid it's too late.
It's never too late.
The worst of us
can be redeemed.
How?
Well, I-I'm
not a vedek...
but it seems to me that
you have to set aside
the things that
led you astray...
ambition, jealousy.
Oh, yes. I have given in
to the temptations of power.
Turn away from temptation.
Yes.
Give yourself over
to the Prophets.
I'll do whatever it takes
to make myself worthy
in their eyes.
Everything will change
once you step down as Kai.
You'll see.
Step down?
I don't understand.
Why would I do that?
Bajor needs me.
E-Eminence...
being in power
is what led you
on the wrong path.
But I've resolved to change.
Don't you see?
Once I have regained
the Prophets' trust
I'll be better able
to serve them if I remain Kai.
If the Prophets wanted
me to step down
surely they would have
told me so.
They don't always use words
to make their wishes known.
Sometimes they speak to us
by touching our hearts
but... only you would know
if they had done that.
But Bajor needs me.
Good night, Eminence.
Yeah... Oh, Damar.
Oh, there you are.
I want you to hear this.
Thot Gor had an
interesting observation
regarding our forces
along the Romulan border.
In his view, we have failed
to take advantage
of several weaknesses
in their defenses.
Is that so?
For instance
the Romulan colony
in the Unroth system
is ripe for attack.
Their long-range-sensor
array is being repaired...
Septimus III has fallen.
Excuse me?
Septimus III.
An entire Cardassian Order has
been wiped out... 500,000 men.
Oh, yes. A great tragedy.
You promised reinforcements.
I promised nothing
of the kind.
I said the situation would be
dealt with, and it was.
By leaving them to be
slaughtered by the Klingons.
If you will calm down
and listen, I will explain.
The sacrifice made
by the 11th Order
will not be in vain.
They forced the Klingons
to commit worthwhile,
valuable troops and resources
to capture a strategically
worthless planet.
I'm glad you agree.
Well, I don't.
You condemned a half a million
loyal Cardassians...
If they were
truly loyal Cardassians
then they died willingly
for the Dominion.
There could be
no greater sacrifice.
How many more sacrifices
will my people be asked to make?
Your people, Damar?
We are all one
with the Dominion...
Vorta, Cardassian,
Jem'Hadar, the Breen.
We all serve the Founders,
and we will all make
whatever sacrifices
they deem necessary.
Thot Gor, would you mind
reiterating your plan
for the Unroth system?
I seem to have lost
my train of thought.
Yes, I know.
It's become increasingly
difficult to get
a full day's work out of him.
The Dax symbiont has lived
for over 300 years
experienced eight lifetimes
and now it's all going to end
with an execution on Cardassia.
Ezri Tigan's contribution
to the Dax legacy
will be to end it.
There is no honor
in self-pity.
You know, Worf,
I have had just about enough
of your little
Klingon aphorisms.
The only reason
I came on this mission
was to save
your miserable life.
So the least you could do
is stop acting like
such a self-righteous targ.
Your motives for rescuing
me are not honorable.
Do you really think that I would
disobey orders and risk my life
so that I could seduce you?
I hate to burst your bubble,
Worf, but it wasn't that good.
Always the barb.
Always the joke.
There was a time when you found
my sense of humor
to be one
of my more endearing qualities.
That was Jadzia, not you.
Are you angry at me
for something that I did
or because I'm not Jadzia?
Let's cut right to the heart
of the matter.
Do you love me?
Me, Ezri?
You are trying to turn this
around and make it about me.
Answer the question.
Do you love me?
I have made my
feelings clear
back on Goralis III.
What is it, Worf?
Could it be
that you're feeling...
just a little guilty
because you don't have
the same feelings for me
that you did for Jadzia?
If that's true...
then maybe we both made
a mistake back on Goralis.
So maybe we both
should be forgiven.
This night would be better spent
preparing ourselves
for the next life
instead of rehashing
the mistakes of this one.
You are right.
What?
I said you are right.
I do not love you
as I loved Jadzia.
There's no crime in that.
Oh, I dishonored myself.
I know how often
I use that word
maybe too often,
but in this case
it is appropriate.
Go on.
From the first moment
you came on the station
I knew you were not Jadzia
and yet... I knew there was
a part of Jadzia
still alive within you.
On Goralis...
I... allowed myself
to see her
instead of you.
I felt the same way.
Part of me...
the part that was your wife...
wanted very much
to be close to you.
I realize
Jadzia saw physical love
differently than I do.
To her, it could mean
many things
but to me,
it was a deeply spiritual act.
When I made love to you...
my motives were not spiritual.
It was an unworthy impulse.
Worf, we're not Gods
or Prophets.
We're people.
We make mistakes.
There is one other thing
I want you to know.
I honestly didn't realize
how I felt about Julian.
I would've never hidden
something like that
from you.
I believe you...
and I do not hold any malice
toward you or Dr. Bashir.
That's good to know.
Friends?
And more.
It appears all we
have left to do is
to be executed.
Sounds like a lazy day to me.
It's time.
There's a Cardassian
patrol ship sitting
in Launch Bay 3-A,
two levels above us.
Its computers have all
the necessary information
to get you past
our security checkpoints.
Why are you doing this?
I want you to give a
message to the Federation.
Tell them they have
an ally on Cardassia.
Why should we trust you?
You can either trust me...
or you can stay here
and be executed.
I vote for option one.
Escaped?!
How could this have happened?
You're the one that
put the Jem'Hadar
in charge
of the detention area.
Thank you for reminding me.
No, I assure you
this is not typical
of our security procedures.
The Founder...
she wishes to see me.
She has to be told about this.
Oh, I'm sure she'll understand
but, if she doesn't...
I look forward
to meeting Weyoun 9.
Eminence...
Anjohl is here.
He claims you called for him.
Show him in.
As you wish.
I remember
when I first saw the gate
of the Celestial Temple.
I was on the Promenade.
When it burst into view, this...
whirlpool of color and light
the people all around me
were in awe.
They said they
could feel the love
of the Prophets
washing over them.
Do you know what I felt, Anjohl?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing...
but I smiled and pretended
I did, because it was
expected of me.
I've never admitted that
to anyone.
I can understand why.
They've never spoken to me...
never offered me guidance...
never trusted me
with the fruits of their wisdom
and now, I'm supposed
to step down as Kai
in order to be blessed by them.
No.
I have worked too hard,
waited too long
to give it all up now.
You shouldn't have to.
Merciful Gods
don't ask their children
to make such sacrifices.
The Prophets have turned
their backs on me...
after all I've done for them
all the pain I've endured
for them.
They're not worthy of you,
Adami.
I'm a patient woman...
but I have run out of patience.
I will no longer serve Gods
who give me nothing in return.
I'm ready to walk the path
the Pah-wraiths
have laid out for me.
I'll walk with you...
and no one...
will be able
to stand against us.
Those who dare to try...
the Federation and
its Vedek puppets
the false Gods and their
precious Emissary...
they'll all be swept aside
like dead leaves
before an angry wind.