Hey, welcome!
Well, I, for one,
never doubted
that you'd be back.
Neither did I.
Don't listen
to him.
He was Mr. Doom
and Gloom
the entire time
you were gone.
Well, I must admit,
I was a bit concerned.
We were all
concerned.
Your well-being was a constant
source of conversation
and speculation.
You see? I told you
they'd miss us.
So, who won
the betting pool?
Morn. He managed to guess
the day you'd be back.
Only missed the time
of your arrival by two hours.
He's amazing.
Don't know how
he does it.
Mr. Worf.
Captain.
I know what you're
going to say.
The answer is yes,
I did leave the station
without your permission, and
yes, I lost a runabout, but...
We'll evaluate
your actions later, old man.
Right now, I'd like to know
everything you learned
about
this Breen-Dominion alliance.
WORF:
I'm afraid
we have very little information
to share with you, Captain.
Weyoun and the others
were more interested
in asking questions
than they were answering them.
Why do you think Damar decided
to help you escape?
I'm not sure, but I can
tell you one thing.
He hates Weyoun.
The Cardassians
are a proud people
but the Dominion treats them
like second-class citizens.
I think
Damar is worried
that this new alliance
with the Breen
is going to weaken
Cardassia's status
with the Dominion even more
but, whatever his reasons,
we owe him our lives.
Maybe one day, you'll be able
to return the favor.
Uh, Doctor
I'd like a complete medical
workup on both of them.
Can't tell you how glad I am
to see you again.
Uh, both--
both... both of you.
( on com )
Kira to Sisko.
Go ahead.
We just received
a priority-one transmission
from Starfleet Command.
The Breen have attacked Earth.
SISKO:
I had a lot of friends
in those buildings.
Starfleet was able
to destroy most
of the Breen
attack force
but by then, most of
the damage had been done.
We must give
the enemy credit.
To launch an attack
on Starfleet Headquarters--
even my people
never attempted that.
We've learned one thing
about the Breen today, Captain.
They're a race of warriors.
That's about
all we know.
Our intelligence reports
are sketchy at best.
Captain, every species
has its weakness.
They're no exception.
Let's hope you're right.
But whatever the weakness is
we better find it soon.
WEYOUN:
There. Do you
see that?
The news from Earth
keeps getting better.
The Federation
casualty report
is being revised
upward once again.
( electronically
distorted voice )
Well put.
The casualties are
merely a bonus.
What matters is that we
have struck fear
into the heart of our enemy
and made them feel weak
and vulnerable.
General
please congratulate
your troops for us.
They've done a superb job.
Don't you agree, Damar?
Superb.
( distorted voice )
It's unfortunate
so few of your ships
survived the assault.
Leave it to you, Damar
to point out
the one cloud in the sky.
( distorted voice )
My thought exactly.
It is a very small price
for such
an important victory.
Now, if you'll excuse me
I must make my report
to the Founder.
By the way, in case Weyoun
neglected to mention it
the Dominion once sang
Cardassia's praises as well.
( distorted voice )
It's really quite simple.
They expected the war
to be over long ago.
It's not,
and for that they blame us.
Now, if the war
isn't ended soon
they'll shift
the blame to you.
( distorted voice )
Well, maybe so,
but win or lose...
I wouldn't turn my back
on Weyoun if I were you.
( coughing )
( clanging )
( sighing )
Kasidy,
what happened?
Uh, that's what I'm
trying to find out.
( sighing )
Ow.
What are you...
you doing?
You don't cook.
I-I know.
I was just making sure.
( sighing ):
Oh, my... my peppers.
I-I know how you like
roasted peppers
in your casserole.
Took me three months
to grow them.
Nobody touches
my peppers.
I'm so sorry.
With all the bad
news about Earth
I wanted to do
something nice for you.
But from now on
you wear the apron
in the family.
You know, that's
a good idea.
Glad you're not mad.
Wouldn't want anything
to ruin our last
few nights together.
Our last few nights together?
My cargo run.
I leave early
next week.
No, you're
not going anywhere.
It's too dangerous.
Ben, the Breen
attacked Earth.
That's not
exactly next door.
We don't know where they're
going to attack next.
I would feel better
if you were closer to me.
Well, that's sweet.
But I'm going anyway.
I can't talk you out of it?
Not a chance.
( door chimes )
Enter.
The information
you requested.
Excellent.
Sit down.
I'm not sure it's
wise for me to stay.
What if the Vorta decides
to pay you a visit?
And what if he does?
He'll see me conferring
with one of my officers.
There's nothing suspicious
about that.
Doesn't seem right--
all this plotting and secrecy.
What are we-- Romulans?
No, we're Cardassians
but right now, Cardassia's
an occupied territory
and to defeat an occupying army
takes careful planning
and secrecy.
Can we really hope
to defeat the Dominion?
With the Breen on their side,
they're stronger than ever.
But we will be fighting
to win back our homes
and our freedom, and that
will make us even stronger.
I remember the day
I heard the news
that Cardassia had
joined the Dominion.
Like everyone else,
I rejoiced.
We were going to be rulers
of the entire Alpha Quadrant.
Instead, we're a
conquered people...
servants in our own land.
All that will soon end.
Now, are you sure we can trust
these officers?
And the troops
under their command.
Still, it's not a
very long list, is it?
It will get longer.
With a victory or two
all Cardassia
will rise up with us.
We'll need to know
the exact location
of the Dominion
weapon emplacements
on Rondac III.
Leave that to me.
Now, I want you
to get a message
to every one
of these officers.
SOLBOR:
Regarding your
scheduled retreat
to the Calash Monastery?
Cancel it.
Very good.
Now, about your appearance
before the
Vedek Assembly?
Cancel that, too.
Cancel an appearance
before the Vedek Assembly?
Just do it.
Cancel everything.
As you wish.
May I ask what, exactly,
you will be doing?
You certainly may not.
But if you must know,
I'll be devoting most of my time
to study and meditation.
( door opening )
I see.
Solbor
I'll have my breakfast
on the balcony this morning.
Eminence, is there
anything you would like?
I'm not hungry.
Oh, but you
really should eat.
After all, Bajor
is only as strong as its Kai.
I said, I'm not hungry.
Do as he asks.
And please...
write a note to the vedeks
expressing my apologies
for having
to postpone our meeting.
I'll see to it immediately.
What a tiresome little man.
Sometimes I think you
forget your place, Anjohl.
Oh, forgive me
if I've offended you in any way.
I am but a moon
made warm
by the light of your sun.
I hope you're a better farmer
than you are a poet.
Something is wrong.
Tell me... what's
bothering you?
Everything-- the prayers,
the rituals, these robes.
I can't keep pretending I follow
the path of the Prophets.
You won't have to.
The Pah-wraiths
are waiting to embrace you.
So you keep saying.
But when is that
going to happen?
As soon as we release them
from the fire caves.
Release them?
But the Prophecies.
What about them?
Well, they warn
that the release
of the Pah-wraiths
will mean the end of Bajor.
The old Bajor, perhaps.
But from its ashes
a new Bajor will arise
and the Restoration will begin.
Who will be left to see it?
Those the Gods find worthy.
It will be the dawn
of paradise
and you, Adami,
are destined to rule it.
You're sure of that?
It is meant to be.
And what will become of you?
Oh, I will be at your side
for as long as you need me.
But first, we have
to release the Pah-wraiths.
But how do we do that?
The answer is in the text
of the Kosst Amojan.
Oh...
It is forbidden for anyone
to open that book.
Yes... anyone
except the Kai.
It is said
to contain great evil.
( laughing )
You have nothing to fear.
I'll be right there with you.
Did I say I was afraid?
( laughs )
Here, this palisade
in the south wall--
if only we could make
this part of the compound
less vulnerable.
What are you talking about?
The south wall
isn't the problem.
They came over the north wall,
by Travis's position.
I know where they came from,
Miles.
I am Travis, remember?
And I say we strengthen
the south wall, the north wall
and any other place that helps
us keep the enemy out.
Then it wouldn't be the battle
of the Alamo, would it?
I don't care.
I just want to win once.
Be Santa Anna.
He wins every time.
What if we put cannons
along the long barracks
like this?
Hey, hey, what do you think
you're doing?!
Do you know how long it took me
to build this thing?
I don't believe the two of you.
Your homeworld has been attacked
the Breen have joined forces
with the Dominion
and here you are,
calmly playing games.
Haven't you ever heard
of grace under pressure, Quark?
Shouldn't you be doing something
more productive?
I just spent 14 hours
recalibrating the station's
weapons array.
And I just did
a complete run-through
of the emergency support team
protocols.
So... you do expect
an attack on the station.
Anything's possible.
What about a moat?
A moat?
Around the Alamo?
Yes. Here, look.
We could widen this stream
maybe make it
a little deeper.
I say we build a moat
around the station.
He is a child.
Miles does have a certain...
cherubic quality.
I was talking
about Dr. Bashir,
and you know it.
Are you certain he's the one?
( sighing )
I'm not certain about anything.
But he is handsome.
WORF:
You deserve more than handsome.
He gets excited
playing with toys.
He knows
how to have a good time.
Besides, it's not exactly a toy.
You heard the Chief.
He spent hours making that.
I see it is hopeless
to try to reason with you.
( sighing )
I know.
Maybe I am in love with him.
Do you think I should tell him
how I feel?
If it will make you happy, yes.
You're a good friend, Worf.
I know.
They are wasting their time.
No matter how much planning
they do
there is no way that they
can defend that mission
against an enemy that numbers
in the thousands
not without more men.
You know, if you want to go
down there and help them...
Just a thought.
Damar.
You're up early.
Am I?
Yes, you are
or you haven't
been to bed yet.
Actually,
I had a very restful sleep.
Did you?
How nice.
I had no idea
the Breen could mobilize
such a large fleet
so quickly.
WEYOUN:
Our new allies
are full of surprises
aren't they?
Hmm.
You know those
refrigeration
suits they wear?
What about them?
I'm sure you've read
the intelligence reports
that say that their homeworld
is a frozen wasteland.
Well, it's not.
The climate on their home
planet is quite comfortable.
Then why do they wear
refrigeration suits?
They won't say.
You see what I mean?
They're full of surprises.
There's something...
different about you
today, Damar.
I can't quite put
my finger on it.
It's almost as if
you're only...
half-dressed.
What are you talking about?
You don't have a
bottle in your hand.
Don't you have anything
better to do than to...?
You've regained your confidence.
I wasn't aware that I'd lost it.
Come now, Damar.
You thought you backed
the wrong side.
You thought the Dominion
was going to lose this war
and drag Cardassia
down with it.
I must admit,
things were looking rather grim.
Perhaps, for a moment or two.
That's no excuse
to lose faith in oneself
or one's allies.
But now...
it's as if you've groped
your way through a dark tunnel
and stepped back out
into the light once again.
You know what
that light's told you?
That the Dominion
will prevail...
that the Federation
will be conquered
and a new era of
peace and prosperity
will blanket the
Alpha Quadrant.
You know me so well.
Really, Damar...
I hope you won't let
that Cardassian-
sized ego of yours
spoil our victory--
and I do mean our victory.
Yours, mine...
And the Breen.
Yes, and the Breen.
We're just one big,
happy family, aren't we?
I like it so much
better when we agree.
Don't you?
The text
of the Kosst Amojan,
as you requested.
Very good.
Well...
put it on my desk.
Eminence, may I speak frankly?
( sighing ):
If you must.
This book has not been removed
from the Archives
not for 700 years.
Your point being?
The knowledge it contains...
about the Pah-wraiths--
it is said to be
very dangerous.
Knowledge is
never dangerous
in the right hands.
There is an old saying--
he who studies evil...
is studied by evil.
I will keep that in mind.
Now give me the book.
Your concern for her Eminence
is appreciated
and acknowledged.
Nevertheless, you
must do as she says.
I will see to it that
no harm comes to her.
There. That should make you
feel better.
I wish it could,
but this man...
one day he comes
onto Deep Space 9
and the next
he's become
your closest advisor.
What do we know of him?
Where did he come from?
What does he want?
I want only to serve the Kai.
This is his idea, isn't it?
To study this hateful book.
Anjohl was sent to me
by the Prophets.
That's all I need to know
and that's all anyone
needs to know.
I have no idea why I was chosen
but who are we to question
the ways of the Prophets?
Perhaps you should go
to the temple
and ask
the Prophets' forgiveness
for questioning their wisdom.
( door opens, closes )
( sighing )
Solbor does not approve of me.
He has served me
well for many years.
And he may serve you well
for many more
if the Pah-wraiths
find him worthy.
Well...?
Aren't you going to open it?
The Pah-wraiths are not evil
but they are powerful
and they're willing to share
that power with you.
The question is:
Do you want it?
Yes.
DUKAT:
This can't be.
This is a trick.
It's not a trick.
Well, then Solbor brought
the wrong book.
He doesn't make those
kinds of mistakes.
The words are here.
They're just
hidden, that's all.
It's up to us to find them.
These are the new
security protocols
you requested.
Very good.
Although, frankly,
I'm not sure
how effective they'll
be against the Breen.
Neither am I.
I just hope we don't
have to find out.
( door opens )
KASIDY:
Benjamin?
You mind explaining this?
Constable, do you
mind if we use your
office for a moment?
Not at all.
Well, it looks like
the Bajoran Freight
and Shipping Authority
wants you to take
a vacation.
A month's paid vacation?
This is your doing,
isn't it?
Let me guess.
The Emissary asked
for a little favor.
I never once mentioned
the word "Emissary."
But you did arrange this.
I'm just trying to keep you
out of harm's way.
Is that such a terrible thing
for a husband to do?
I told you.
I don't need or want
that kind of protection.
I want you to call
whoever you called
and have them put me
back on the active list.
Kasidy, it's only for a month.
I don't care
if it's only for a day.
How would you like it if I
called Admiral Ross and said
"Oh, do me a favor.
Please don't send
my husband on any dangerous
missions this month"?
Look, that's not the same thing.
It is from where I'm standing.
My job is just as important
to me as your job is to you.
I know that.
( chuckles )
What's so funny?
Marriage-- it changes
everything.
If you're not careful
that could be you and Kira.
Huh.
( door opens )
Here are the other volumes
you wanted.
Thank you, Solbor.
You may go now.
Eminence
I must inform you
that the archivists
are very...
You heard the Kai.
Leave us.
They're wondering
why you need to consult
so many of these dark texts.
You may tell them that their Kai
works for the good of Bajor.
Now leave me.
I have work to do.
Why are you still here?
What would you like me to do?
Go away.
I don't understand.
I must concentrate.
But, Your Eminence...
Not another word.
Very well.
They're beautiful.
Then you forgive me?
Uh, that depends.
Have you talked to Bajoran
Freight and Shipping?
You're back on the active list.
Then I forgive you.
But, from here on in...
I'm not to interfere
with your work
unless you tell me to.
Or it's absolutely
necessary.
I'm just joking.
You'd better be.
What's that for?
The flowers.
And for being big enough
to admit when you're wrong.
( door chimes )
Ah, that must be Quark
with the necklace.
The necklace?
Just in case
the flowers didn't work.
( laughing )
Ben, the Breen have launched
a counteroffensive
against our forces
in the Chin'toka system.
SISKO:
Have they broken through?
In two places.
When do I leave?
This is bad... very bad.
You say that every time we take
the Defiant into battle.
Impulse manifold
purged and clear.
If we lose the
Chin'toka system
we lose our only foothold
in the Dominion territory.
I think that
qualifies as bad.
Well, we haven't lost it yet.
Initiating impulse
pre-start sequence.
Microfusion
generators on line.
But the Breen, they
seem unstoppable.
First Earth,
now Chin'toka?
Ensign, no one
is unstoppable.
Collimate
the nadion emitters.
Collimation sequence
in progress.
What more can I say, Miles,
but I'm sorry?
Dilithium matrix
is aligned and calibrated.
Just be a bit
more careful.
That's all I ask.
Opening antimatter
injector ports.
Trouble in paradise?
It was nothing.
Emergency life-support
and damage control systems
standing by.
I wouldn't call it nothing.
Autonomous guidance system
initialized and active.
He lost Travis.
Hmm. Sounds serious.
Verify astrometric
database.
BASHIR:
Miles built this Alamo model
replete with small figures.
Quite spectacular, actually.
Datasets loaded and verified.
Anyway, he was showing it to me
in Quark's when we--
rather, I-- accidentally
misplaced Colonel Travis.
Phaser safeties engaged.
Can't you make another one?
What, so he can
lose it again?
Field stabilizers
on line.
Well, that's what happens
when you share your toys.
Synchronizing
warp plasma flow.
It's not a toy.
It's a model built to scale.
BASHIR:
He really did
a fantastic job.
O'BRIEN:
Nacelles holding
at pre-warp threshold.
BASHIR:
Miles, look...
He plays with toys.
It's a model.
With little figures.
Captain on the Bridge!
Commander.
WORF:
Weapons array is on line.
Phasers are fully charged.
Quantum torpedo launchers
are loaded and standing by.
Colonel, set a course
to rendezvous
with the Federation
Assault Fleet.
Course set.
Take us out.
Airlocks are sealed.
Releasing docking clamps.
Where are you going
with those?
I'm returning these
books to the Archives.
On whose authority?
I believe
her Eminence has finished.
Put them back.
How dare you use
that tone with me...
( groans )
I'll put them back.
( whispering ):
Wake up, my love.
There's work to be done.
Oh, Anjohl.
I must have dozed off.
You're tired.
It's understandable.
I haven't made
much progress.
You'll find the answers
we're looking for.
It's just a matter of time.
Oh, I'm so glad
you're here.
Hmm.
I'll see that you're
brought something to eat.
Hmm?
According to the latest
battle reports
it looks as if the Dominion
is going to retake
Chin'toka.
A few months ago,
the thought of the Federation
being driven
from Cardassian soil
would've been a cause
for celebration
but the Dominion victories
are no longer our victories.
Now, are our troops
in position?
They're awaiting your command.
Excellent.
We attack in seven hours.
We're going to lose
many fine soldiers.
At least they'll be dying
for Cardassia
and not the Dominion.
WEYOUN:
The Federation
reinforcements
are approaching
Chin'toka.
The more of them,
the better.
Founder,
it concerns me
to have you this
close to the front.
You're concern is noted.
But this is one battle
I intend to see firsthand.
Yes.
It should be
most gratifying.
ROMULAN ( on com ):
Romulan attack wings
three and nine
have reached the line
of deployment.
FEDERATION OFFICER:
Federation fighter squadrons
seven and ten,
break into sections
and stand by to begin
reconnaissance sweep.
MARTOK:
Lead units
assume attack positions.
Advance to contact.
Sir, they've locked weapons
on us.
All auxiliary power
to forward shields.
Colonel, attack pattern delta.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, quantum torpedoes.
Target locked.
Fire.
WORF:
Target locked.
Launchers one
and two standing by.
Fire.
( alarm beeping )
What the hell is...?!
( yelling )
( alarm beeping )
We've lost power to the helm.
The com's out.
So are weapons.
Primary computer systems
are off-line.
( yelling )
Manual controls are frozen.
Chief.
I can't get
anything
back on line.
Somehow, they're draining
all our power.
NOG:
The fire-suppression system's
off-line!
WORF:
Use the manual extinguishers.
NOG:
I'm on it.
EZRI:
We're venting
plasma coolant
from over eight
separate EPS ruptures.
The air's becoming toxic,
Captain.
Sir, the ablative armor
is starting to buckle.
We have hull breaches
on decks 3 and 4.
O'BRIEN:
Without power for the
emergency force fields
there's no way to seal them.
Abandon ship.
( alarm blares )
SISKO:
You heard me.
Everyone get to the escape pods.
Now.
( alarm continues )
Captain...
She's a fine ship.
No one will argue
with that.
But like you say,
it's time to go.
Poor Captain Sisko.
I believe he was quite fond
of that ship.
Founder, I'm happy to report
that the Chin'toka system
is ours once again.
A step in the right direction.
Send my compliments
to the Breen.
I'm certain
that will please them greatly.
Really?
I have no idea what would please
the Breen, nor do I care
as long as they fight and win.
I will not tolerate
defeat any longer.
Nor will I.
All those escape pods...
so small... so vulnerable.
I'll order their destruction
immediately.
No.
Let them return
to the Federation.
Those pods are filled with
frightened, demoralized troops.
Troops that will spread fear
throughout the Federation
with tales
of what happened here today.
The Founder is wise.
There...
now, don't you
feel better?
Much.
Thank you, Anjohl.
I'm here to serve
you any way I can.
( door opens )
Get away from her.
DUKAT:
What?
Eminence, that man
is not Anjohl Tennan.
What are you talking about?
Anjohl Tennan
died nine years ago
in the labor camp
at Batal.
I warned you
not to trust him.
I had a sample
of his DNA sequenced.
He's not even a Bajoran.
He's a Cardassian.
We were brought
together for a cause.
A great cause.
Our destinies
are linked.
SOLBOR:
Don't listen to him.
Look at him.
Don't you recognize the face
of your enemy?
It's Gul Dukat.
Oh, it can't be.
He lied to you...
used you.
It's not true.
I don't know why
you wanted to do this--
for what evil purpose--
but it's not going to work.
He doesn't understand, Adami.
He couldn't possibly
understand the love
of the Pah-wraiths.
The love of the Pah-wraiths...
you're trying to release them.
That's why
you wanted the text
of the Kosst Amojan.
Solbor, listen to me.
All I want is to bring about
the Restoration.
You've betrayed the Prophets.
You've betrayed us all.
Try to understand.
The Pah-wraiths--
they are the true Gods.
You must be stopped.
Solbor... I beg you... no!
( yells )
It'll be all right.
Don't touch me.
My life is over.
The Pah-wraiths sent you
to destroy me.
On the contrary,
they sent me to save you.
Lies.
Nothing but Cardassian lies.
And to think I let you touch me.
The book.
I must destroy it.
There!
You see?
The Pah-wraiths have judged you
and found you worthy.
Their secrets
are now your secrets
to do with as you please.
Take their gift and use it.
Seize the power they're
offering you.
What about Solbor?
I'll take care
of the body.
The Defiant was the finest ship
I ever commanded.
There'll never be
another one like her.
It may take a while, Ben
but I'll get you another ship,
I promise you that.
I just wish I knew
how we were going to neutralize
the Breen energy dissipaters.
We need to buy
some time.
Time may be the one thing
we don't have.
KIRA:
Captain, we're monitoring
a transmission
from Cardassian space.
I think you're going
to find it interesting.
...and so two years ago
our government signed a treaty
with the Dominion.
In it, the Dominion
promised to extend
Cardassia's influence
throughout the Alpha Quadrant.
In exchange,
we pledged ourselves
to join the war
against the Federation
and its allies.
Cardassians have never
been afraid of war.
A fact we've proven time and
again over these past two years.
Seven million of our brave
soldiers have given their lives
to fulfill our part
of the agreement.
And what has the Dominion
done in return?
Nothing.
We've gained no new territories.
In fact, our influence
throughout the Quadrant
has diminished.
And to make matters worse
we are no longer masters
in our own home.
Travel anywhere in Cardassia
and what do you find?
Jem'Hadar... Vorta...
and now Breen.
Instead of the invaders,
we have become the invaded.
Our allies have conquered us
without firing a single shot.
Well, no longer.
This morning, detachments
of the Cardassian First
Third and Ninth Orders
attacked a Dominion outpost
on Rondac III.
This assault marks
the first step
toward the liberation
of our homeland...
Colonel, see if you can get
confirmation on that.
...from the true oppressors
of the Alpha Quadrant.
I call upon Cardassians
everywhere...
resist.
Resist today.
Resist tomorrow.
Resist till the last Dominion
soldier has been driven
from our soil.
It's confirmed.
Our cloning facility
on Rondac III
has been destroyed.
I could be the last Weyoun.
That's why he picked
that target.
I want Damar and the rest
of these traitors
found and eliminated.
I'll see to it immediately.
I don't care how
many Cardassians
you have to kill.
Find Damar.
Is that clear?
( distorted voice )
I'm going to hold
you to that.
( distorted voice )
Captain, our listening posts
have confirmed the
attack on Rondac.
Damar may have just bought
us some precious time...
if the Dominion doesn't
track him down too quickly.
We need to find a way
to help him.
Legate Damar may be the key
to saving the Alpha Quadrant.