Basically, we stumbled on it
by accident.
At Chin'toka,
our entire fleet was disabled
when the Breen engaged
their energy-dampening weapon.
311 ships... Federation, Romulan
and Klingon... all lost power.
But one didn't... a bird-of-prey
called the Ki'tang.
Why?
What was different
about the Ki'tang?
We're not really sure.
The only thing we can figure
is that just prior
to the engagement
their Chief Engineer
adjusted the tritium
intermix to compensate
for a containment problem
in the warp core.
I've ordered every ship
in the Klingon fleet
to adjust its reactor
the same way.
Our vessels are
of a different design.
Can this technique be adapted
to protect them as well?
Unfortunately, no.
Your ships are still vulnerable,
and so are ours.
I've sent everything we know
about the Breen weapon
to the Romulan Ministry
of Science
and to Starfleet Engineering
but realistically,
it's going to take awhile
before they can figure out a way
to protect our ships.
Thank you, Mr. O'Brien.
Well, gentlemen, it seems
as if the Klingon fleet
is the only thing that stands
between us and the Dominion.
What have we come to?
By tomorrow, we'll have
1,500 Klingon vessels
ready for deployment.
With the Breen, the Cardassians
and the Jem'Hadar
you're still outnumbered
20 to one.
I am aware of that, General.
Obviously, the Klingons can't go
head-to-head with the Dominion
but they may be able
to keep them distracted.
We'll operate
in small battle groups
going in under cloak,
engaging the enemy
and trying to provoke them
into pursuit.
With any luck
they'll be able to keep
the Dominion off-balance
and prevent them
from launching an offensive.
For how long?
They can't keep them
at bay forever.
No, they can't
but, fortunately,
we're not the only ones
the Dominion has
to contend with right now.
Damar's resistance movement.
What's left of them.
Half his troops were killed
in the assault on Rondac.
They may have failed
to capture Rondac
but their attack sent a message
to the Cardassian people.
If the rebels can show them
that they have a chance
of succeeding
their support will grow.
Does the rebellion
have a chance of succeeding?
Yes, but they have
to adjust their tactics...
concentrate on small-scale,
hit-and-run attacks, sabotaging
key facilities.
Damar's a by-the-book soldier.
Does he have any experience
waging this kind of campaign?
No, he doesn't...
which is why we have
to send him someone who does.
You want me
to go behind enemy lines
and teach a bunch of Cardassians
how to be resistance fighters?
I'm aware of the irony,
but the tactics you used
to drive the Cardassians
off Bajor
are exactly what the situation
calls for.
To work with Damar...
When he killed Ziyal,
he murdered an innocent girl
that I considered
a part of my family.
You're going to have to put
your personal feelings aside.
Now, whether you like Damar
or not is irrelevant.
We need him.
The Dominion knows
they have to stop his rebellion
before it spreads,
and it's up to you
to see that they don't.
It's as simple as that.
Yes, sir.
I understand that Damar
and his men went into hiding
after the attack on Rondac.
Any idea how to locate them?
I suggest you talk
to Mr. Garak about that.
Garak?
He still has contacts
on Cardassia.
If I were you, I would ask him
to join your team.
He might be useful.
Damar and Garak...
should be
an interesting mission.
It's very difficult
to keep a supply
of synthetic organs on hand
in a battlefield situation.
You never know how many livers
you're going to need.
Or, uh... how many hearts.
I can imagine
but, uh, what does that
have to do with me?
Well, the holy grail
of organ replacement
is to be able to find a way
to inject the patient with
undifferentiated tissue
so that it can become
whatever organ is needed.
The only problem is...
Doctor, get to the point.
I need to borrow...
a cup... of goo.
Excuse me?
Please?
I'll give it back.
You see, I need to study
your morphogenic matrix
so that I can synthesize
organic tissue
that can change form
the way your cells do.
To use for organ replacement.
Exactly.
Well, can't you just...
oh... scan me, or something?
I need a sample.
It's for a good cause.
All right, Doctor.
Just a tad more.
Thank you.
I am going to want that back
as soon as Kira and I
return from our mission.
Oh. You're going with her?
She thought I might be useful.
When do you leave?
As soon as Garak
can locate Damar.
I am very concerned.
It's not like Solbor
to disappear this way.
Please do whatever
it takes to find him.
Yes, Eminence.
Well done.
I almost believed you myself.
How like a Cardassian
to find amusement
in an old man's death.
You don't know how much I
regret having to kill him.
He was going to expose us.
No one can be allowed
to stand in our way.
Remember your place, Dukat.
I thought my place
was in your bed.
That was before
I knew who you were.
Adami...
I'm not the same man
I was during the occupation.
The Pah-wraiths
have changed me.
But they can't change
what you did.
Do you really think I could
let myself be touched by a man
whose hands are stained
with the blood of my people?
When we do release
the Pah-wraiths
from the fire caves
your hands will be stained
as well.
The Pah-wraiths will spare those
whom they find worthy.
The rest are of no consequence.
You've been
studying that for days.
Perhaps I could help.
The text of the Kosst Amojan
is for my eyes alone.
Well, have you learned
what we have to do
to release the Pah-wraiths?
Only that
it's not a simple matter.
Leave me.
I've had enough
of your distractions.
When is Gowron's ship
due to arrive?
In the morning.
Martok seems a little nervous
about the ceremony.
Chancellor Gowron is traveling
all the way from Kronos
to induct him into
the Order of Kahless.
I'd be nervous, too.
Come in.
Good news.
Garak was able to contact Damar.
He's provided us
with his location
and has requested assistance
as soon as possible.
So, with your permission,
I'd like to depart
first thing tomorrow.
By all means.
Uh... there is one other thing.
Yes, Mr. Garak?
Damar expressed concern
when I told him
that Colonel Kira would
be leading this mission.
Well, if he wants
to defeat the Dominion
he's going to have to put
his personal feelings aside.
He's certainly willing
to do that.
He knows the value
of your skills.
Damar is concerned
that his men
will see your uniform
as an affront.
We Cardassians
are a proud people.
Losing Bajor
to a ragtag band of terrorists...
no offense...
was a humiliation.
Simply put,
taking on a Bajoran officer
as an advisor would
undermine his authority.
Sorry, Colonel.
We'll have to find someone else
to head up the mission.
No... sir.
Colonel Kira is
the best person for the job.
There's another way
around this problem.
I don't know.
Do you really think it'll make
a difference to the Cardassians
that you've been given
a Starfleet commission?
You're still a Bajoran.
A Bajoran with the authority
to speak on behalf
of the Federation.
You realize you're going
to have to do something
about your uniform as well.
I was afraid
you were going to say that.
Well?
It's a little drab.
This is how I appeared
when I worked
for the Cardassians.
Ah, well, it should
put them at ease, anyway.
I wonder
if Dr. Bashir could help us
with that nose of yours?
I'm only willing to go so far.
Damar's men are just going
to have to get used
to the idea of having me around.
Oh, they'll tolerate you
to a point.
If I were you,
I'd watch my back.
I'll see you in the morning.
You see the problem.
Our food supplies
are running low.
We'll have to cut
back on rations
until we can get ahold
of some food replicators.
When I spoke to Garak,
I told him to bring some.
Federation food replicators?
We are in no position
to turn down help
no matter where it comes from.
Taking help from the
Federation is bad enough
but having to take it from
that Bajoran terrorist...
Kira Nerys has certain skills
she's willing to teach us...
skills we need if we're going
to defeat the Dominion.
I can't believe
what I'm hearing.
When we were stationed
on Terok Nor
you used to spend hours
telling me
how much you despised her.
I did hate her.
That's a luxury I can no longer
afford and neither can you.
I need your support in this,
my friend.
General.
Mr. Worf.
Welcome to Deep Space 9,
Chancellor.
It's been too long, Captain.
You know Admiral Ross.
We met at Khitomer.
Admiral, of course.
Martok...
the man I came to honor.
The son of Mogh...
Chancellor.
They say you've made him
part of your House.
That's true.
Then what is past is past.
If Martok considers you
his brother, that's all
I need to know.
Come... I brought a barrel
of the finest bloodwine
and it must be drunk tonight!
The vintage... 2309, I hope.
I guess we're not invited.
Anyway, I finally
tracked her down to Quark's
and I asked her flat out
"Ezri, why are you avoiding me?"
She was just about to answer
when I got called away.
I haven't noticed her
avoiding you.
You sure
you're not imagining things?
Our paths haven't crossed
in days.
Well, it's a big station.
The truth is, you want
to spend time with her
so it seems
that she's never around.
There's something going on
and I'm going to find out
what it is when she gets here.
I told her I'd like to discuss
the results
of her last medical exam.
Isn't that unethical
or something?
Well...
Is that Odo?
Part of him, anyway.
Oh, never mind.
I don't want to know.
Computer
begin a morphogenic
enzyme analysis.
Hi.
Ezri.
Um, you wanted to see me?
Yes. Come on in.
Well, um, it was good
running into you.
I haven't seen you in days.
So...
You said something
about my test results?
Of course.
Here it is.
You know, uh...
we never finished
our conversation
the other day.
Our conversation?
Yes, at Quark's.
You were telling me, uh,
why, uh, you were avoiding me.
Well, I guess now
is as good a time as any.
Well, it goes back
to when Worf and I
were held prisoner by the Breen.
We spent a lot of time together.
Naturally.
And you can imagine
that it would bring up
all sorts of old feelings.
Sure.
And well, one thing led
to another and...
Ezri, you don't have
to say anymore.
But I want to.
No, really.
Um, I wish you both
all the happiness
in the world.
Who?
You and Worf.
No, Julian, that's not...
Ezri, there's no need
to explain.
No, you don't understand.
What I'm trying
to tell you is that...
I'm in love...
Oh, my God.
What?
Julian, what's wrong?
I was running a scan
on the sample you left me
when I noticed
something... unusual.
Unusual in what way?
The disease
that's killing your people...
you're infected.
My guess is you became infected
when you linked
with the female shape-shifter.
Are you sure about this?
He doesn't have any symptoms.
So far, but from what I can tell
the virus is replicating quickly
and it may not be long before
symptoms start to surface.
Well, we have to get you
back to the station.
No. We have a mission
to accomplish.
I intend to see it through.
Odo...
It's all right.
At this point,
there's not much I can do
but I feel confident
that's going to change.
What do you mean?
I'm running a series of tests
on the sample that you left me
and I've asked Starfleet Medical
to send the results
from the tests they ran on you
a few years ago.
By comparing the results
I might be able to figure out
how this virus works
and that may well lead
to a cure.
Thank you, Julian.
We should be crossing
into Dominion space
in just a few minutes.
I'd better scan
for enemy patrols.
What have you been keeping
from me, my sweet?
What dark secrets?
Dukat!
Adami... help me.
You fool!
I can't see.
I warned you...
the text of the Kosst Amojan
is for my eyes alone.
Today, we honor
our brother Martok
in the manner...
Kahless taught us.
I accept this honor
in the name
of the House of Martok
and ask only to be allowed
to continue to serve the Empire.
Martok!
We're next.
Martok! Martok! Martok!
You're kidding.
I wish I were.
Martok! Martok!
You have done well.
Thank you for the help,
my friend.
It still stings.
That's what the bloodwine
is for.
Congratulations, General.
Martok...
how does it feel to be
the most famous warrior
in the Empire?
I am grateful for the
opportunity to serve.
And you've served well
but you've borne
the burden of this war
for a long time.
I do it gladly
and I'll keep on fighting
until the victory is ours.
No, my friend.
I can't ask you
to carry this weight forever.
It's time for me to take
a more active role in this war.
As of today, I'm assuming
direct command of our forces.
Chancellor, I...
I don't understand.
Are you unsatisfied with the way
I have performed my duties?
Would I have given you
the Star of Kahless
if I was not satisfied?
You should be happy
you're a warrior again.
No more meetings,
no more reports to file.
You'll be out there
savoring the heat of battle.
I envy you.
I intend to see an end
to this war, and soon.
The Dominion will rue
the day they heard my name!
No, I don't want to talk
to Lieutenant Douglas.
I've already talked
I need a copy
of these test results.
My patient's life is at stake.
I wish I could help
but as I said, the files
you requested are classified.
Why would Odo's medical records
be classified?
They are.
That's all I know.
I want to talk
to your supervising officer.
You did... Lieutenant Douglas.
Then I want to talk to her
supervising officer, Ensign.
I'll patch you through
but he's going to tell you
the same thing.
Commander Hilliard here.
Ah, Commander.
I was hoping you could, uh,
sort out this situation for me.
I realize that the files
I requested are classified
but given the circumstances,
I was hoping you would be able
to understand the need
for some expediency.
Of course.
You wouldn't mind answering
a few questions?
Um... of course not,
if it's necessary.
Now, you've requested Security
Chief Odo's medical records
from Stardate...
49419, sir.
And you state
that he has contracted
the morphogenic virus
that's infected the Founders.
Correct.
How did he contract it?
Presumably when he linked
with one of them, sir.
You're saying that he's been
in contact with the enemy?
Yes, but not recently.
It happened over a year ago.
Now, I assume that you've done
your own scans of Odo
over the years.
Of course.
Then why do you need ours?
To use as a point of comparison
in hopes of finding a cure, sir.
A cure?
That's right.
Is there anything else, sir?
No. No, that pretty much
covers it.
Good. So, um,
when can I expect to receive
a copy of these files?
I'm afraid
those files are classified.
But... I thought
you just asked me
all these questions in order
to clear me to receive them.
No, no, you misunderstood.
I can't release those files
to anyone that doesn't have
Sigma Nine Clearance.
Listen, I don't give a damn
about Sigma Nine Clearance!
All I care about is finding
a cure for this disease!
I fail to see
why you're so determined
to cure a disease
that infects our enemy.
We're at war, Doctor.
The Founders have nothing
to do with it.
Odo's life is at stake!
Odo, who by your own admission
has been known to consort
with the enemy.
Sir, you have to understand
the circumstances.
I don't care
about the circumstances.
If you find a cure
there's a good chance
it'll fall into Dominion hands.
That's a risk that Starfleet
Medical is not willing to take.
Request for the files is denied.
Now, if I were you,
I would drop this matter.
Otherwise, I'll have to refer it
to Starfleet Security.
Sounds like a typical bureaucrat
flexing his muscles.
No, it was more than that.
He practically accused me
of being a traitor.
Made it sound like I was
in league with the Dominion
just because I
wanted to help Odo.
Maybe the attack on Starfleet
Headquarters has him spooked.
You know, guys like Hilliard
are used to sitting behind
their desks, not under them.
If only I could get ahold
of that file.
Maybe the Captain
can request it.
Well, does he have Sigma Nine
Clearance, whatever that is?
For Odo's sake,
we better hope so.
Welcome to the headquarters
of the Cardassian
Liberation Front.
It's been a long time.
Yes, it has.
Did you bring the
supplies we requested?
Food replicators, weapons...
I think you'll find
everything you've asked for.
Excellent.
The Cardassian people
won't forget
the Federation's generosity.
How nice.
And now that the formalities
are over with
let's try to remember
that our enemy
is the Dominion
and not each other.
I don't need to be reminded
who my enemies are.
A resistance organization
is structured into cells...
autonomous groups
of ten or 20 people.
That way, if anyone
gets captured
their ability to compromise
the entire organization
is limited.
They can't be forced to name
names that they don't know.
The Obsidian Order
worked the same way.
We have to decentralize
your operation.
Having all your men
in one place is just too risky.
If we scatter our resources
we won't be able
to defend ourselves
against a Dominion assault.
And if you stay in one place,
they can wipe out
your entire resistance movement
in one attack.
Smaller groups are safer.
They're harder to track down.
I'll have my men investigate
possible locations
for other bases.
Good.
Now, Odo and Garak
have been looking over
your intelligence reports
and they came up with a list
of vulnerable facilities
for us to target.
The weapons depot
on Adarak Prime
is protected by only a single
garrison and there's
a weakness in their
perimeter defenses.
A small group could infiltrate
the compound and disable...
Adarak Prime is defended
by a Cardassian garrison.
That's correct.
You expect us to attack
our own people?
If necessary, yes.
That's out of the question.
I agree.
We'll limit ourselves
to targets defended
by the Jem'Hadar and the Breen.
Well, believe me,
I understand how you feel.
During the occupation
I didn't want to attack
any facility
that had a Bajoran
working in it, but I did it
because they were collaborators.
They were working
with the enemy.
We're not Bajorans.
We don't kill our own.
Well, then, you might as well
just give up right now
because the minute
that the Dominion realizes
that you will not attack
your own people
they will station
a Cardassian
at every base they have.
She's right.
The Founders won't hesitate
to play your own people
against you.
Anyone who is not
fighting with you
is fighting against you.
You were saying
the Adarak perimeter
defenses are vulnerable.
Damar!
Not another word, Rusot.
Continue.
We would need to disable
the garrison's
security protocols.
I believe
that's where I step in.
I'd love to have seen
Hilliard's face
when he realized Captain Sisko
had Sigma Nine Clearance.
So... is the file worth
all the trouble
you had to go through?
There's more data here
than I expected.
Starfleet Medical
certainly were thorough.
Oh, by the way...
what happened with you and Ezri?
Don't ask.
Go on.
Actually,
she got involved with Worf.
What?
She told you that?
Well, not in so many words.
Julian...
I had a drink with Worf
the other day.
He told me that he and Ezri
were just friends.
You must have
misunderstood her.
I suppose it's possible.
I mean, she didn't exactly
come out and say it.
Well, did you at least
find out
why she's been avoiding you?
No.
That's odd.
What?
The dispersal pattern
in this resonance scan...
I've seen it before.
What do you mean?
When I first came to the station
I had to familiarize myself
with Odo's physiology.
Dr. Mora was kind enough
to share his data with me.
This looks like the scan
he did when he first found Odo.
Are you sure?
There's a lot of numbers there.
I saw it with my own eyes
not seven years ago.
Huh. You really are
genetically enhanced,
aren't you?
According to the date
this scan was done when Odo
was at Starfleet Medical.
Two different scans can't have
exactly the same
dispersal patterns?
It's impossible.
Someone took Dr. Mora's
results and built up
a phony medical
workup around them.
This isn't Odo's file.
They sent a fake.
Oh, I can't believe
Starfleet Medical
would actually
make up a fake file
just to throw you off.
You're right.
It isn't something
Starfleet Medical would do.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Section 31.
An organization that's prepared
to do whatever it takes
to "protect" the Federation
wouldn't even blink
at doing something like this.
They don't want me
to find a cure.
They're afraid the Founders
will get hold of it.
And to keep that
from happening...
they're willing to let Odo die.
First he gives me a medal,
then he takes over my command.
It makes no sense.
Our people have come to see you
as a savior of the Empire.
That is something
Gowron cannot tolerate.
He wants to be its savior.
What's he afraid of?
That I'm going
to challenge his position?
I have no interest in politics.
I'm a soldier.
By the hand of Kahless...
I've earned my position.
I've risen through the ranks,
fought countless battles
and what has he done?
Schemed and plotted
his way to power.
His military experience
is limited.
He is not
half the tactician you are.
Many brave warriors have given
their lives in this war.
Whatever Gowron's motives are,
it is our duty to help him
defeat the Dominion.
We owe it
to our fallen comrades.
I am honored
to be part of your House.
Hmm...
Well...
I had better gather my things.
This office belongs
to Gowron now.
How's the food?
Replicated.
Are you going to ask him or not?
I wouldn't recommend it.
It's a legitimate
question, Garak.
Maybe I just don't think
it's a proper subject
for discussion
not if we're all supposed
to be getting along.
Well, if you won't ask him,
I will.
Odo.
When you were the Head
of Security on Terok Nor
what did you think
was going to happen
to the Bajoran
prisoners you arrested?
You don't have to answer that.
Why not?
It's a legitimate question.
Only if you want
to provoke an argument.
Just as I said.
I expected
that my prisoners would
be dealt with justly...
but I soon came to realize
that Cardassians have
little interest in justice.
Ah.
Well, then, why didn't
you resign in protest?
What are you getting at?
Nerys, don't.
I believe you've
struck a nerve.
Apparently, Commander Kira
doesn't like to be reminded
that her lover collaborated
with her enemies.
Odo wasn't a collaborator.
I suppose that depends
on your definition
of collaborator.
Nerys...
it isn't worth it.
Odo's right, Commander.
I guess we have
a difference of opinion.
You don't know
how lucky you are.
Oh? Why is that?
She would have killed you.
I only wish she had tried.
Well, I'm glad
we're in agreement.
If you want to knock over
some supplies, be my guest.
You did the right thing, Nerys.
The Dominion is our enemy
not Rusot.
I don't need you
to remind me of that!
Oh...
I'm sorry. I'm...
I'm sorry.
It's just, uh...
it's just so hot in here.
Well...
the Cardassians
do love the heat.
I don't.
I'm going to go see
if I can find a cooling unit.
I'll come with you.
It's all right.
I promise I won't hit anyone.
I'll hold you to that.
Now, you're not going
to believe this.
Believe what?
Damar actually had a cooling
unit waiting for us.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I was just worried
that you might have had
another run-in with Rusot.
Don't worry.
I'm going to keep a cool head.
Assuming, of course,
I can get this thing to work.
Adami...
are you there?
I'm here.
I spoke with the doctor.
She says she can find
nothing wrong with your eyes.
Then she's incompetent.
A Cardassian doctor
would have cured me by now.
You still don't understand,
do you?
The Pah-wraiths
have taken your sight
in punishment
for your arrogance.
Only they can
give it back to you.
I meant them no disrespect.
I only wanted to study the book
to see if I could help you learn
how to release them.
You wanted to see
if you could do it without me.
Well, you can't.
Pray with me, Adami.
Help me earn
the Pah-wraiths' forgiveness.
I'm afraid you'll have
to do that on your own.
Door.
Deputy Bodan will show you out.
"Show me out..."
I don't understand.
Well, you need
a lesson in humility.
I'm going to see
that you get it.
By putting me out on the street?
You'll find the Bajoran people
are very kind.
A blind beggar will elicit
their sympathies, I'm certain
and with any luck, you'll earn
enough to eat, and perhaps
even enough
for shelter each night.
You're not...
you're not serious?
You may return
when you've
proven yourself worthy
and your sight
has been restored.
Bodan.
Adami, lis...
Adami...
Adami, listen to me, please!
Adami!
You see?
Enter.
Come in, come in.
I've been studying
the strategic situation.
I want to share my thoughts
with you.
Of course.
Come.
The Dominion is deploying
its fleet in preparation
for a final offensive.
They're destroying
our ships one by one.
We must hold the line
until the Federation
and Romulan fleets
become operational again.
No, don't you see?
That's exactly what the enemy
is expecting.
The time to act is now.
What are you proposing,
Chancellor?
We're going on the offensive.
Starting tomorrow,
I'm sending sorties
deep into enemy territory
to strike at the very heart
of the Dominion.
But we are barely
holding the line as it is.
We need every ship we have
to defend the border.
What's wrong with you two?
Don't you understand?
We must seize the day!
We are outnumbered 20 to one.
What of it?
The element of surprise
will be on our side.
Chancellor, in my opinion...
Did I ask your opinion?
Trust me, my friends.
I can see it all so clearly.
While our allies sit
and do nothing
the Klingon Empire
will score the final triumph
over the Dominion.
We'll be the saviors
of the Alpha Quadrant.
The glory will be ours...
and ours alone.
I don't know, Julian.
If Section 31
is involved with this
maybe we should
tell the Captain.
We've been over this, Miles.
If we tell him, he'll have to
report it to Starfleet Command.
31 will certainly get wind of it
and once they realize we've
figured out the files are fake
they'll take steps to make
sure we don't find a cure.
Hmm. I see your point.
What steps do you think
they might take?
Believe me, we don't
want to find out.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Is that coffee?
I figured you were probably
working on a way to help Odo.
I thought... this is
the least I can do.
How did you know Odo was ill?
I hear things.
Yeah, well, keep it
under your hat, will you?
Why?
Just do it.
All right.
All right, do you
still want the coffee?
Odo would be touched
if he knew you were doing this.
You're not going
to tell him, are you?
It'll be our little secret.
Good luck.
Here you go.
Hang on, hang on.
I'm... just trying to figure out
when Odo became infected.
I analyzed the sample he left
and mapped out the life
cycle of the virus
and programmed the computer to
calculate just how long it took
for the virus to reach
its present level
of concentration.
Well, that makes sense.
Well, according to that
he was infected
over two years ago?
More than that.
I just don't understand.
I assumed he became infected
when he linked
with the female shape-shifter.
But if it happened that long ago
how come he's never shown
any symptoms before?
Good question.
Got it.
Stardate 49419.
Almost three years ago.
Wait a minute.
49419...
That's the day that Odo
was at Starfleet Medical.
Are you sure?
Yes.
My God, no wonder Hilliard
wouldn't let me see the file.
Section 31 must have created
the virus, infected Odo
and then used him
as a carrier.
So that when he linked
with another changeling
he'd pass it on.
Eventually, the entire
race would be infected.
31 isn't just trying to stop
us from finding a cure.
They're trying to
cover up the fact
that they set out
to commit genocide.
Well, if they gave
Odo this disease
then they must have a cure.
We have to find a way
to get our hands
on that cure.
Huh... before 31 gets
their hands on us.