KIRA:
There, right there.
The explosion began
at the intercooler
matrix
and your men were supposed
to plant the bomb
here at the secondary
plasma relay.
What difference
does it make?
The ship was destroyed.
GARAK:
The intercooler was
the obvious choice
for sabotage.
Their security checks
could have found the bomb
and disarmed it before
the ship left orbit.
But they didn't find it.
That isn't
the point.
Your men ignored
their instructions
and their training.
Let us not lose
sight of the fact
that the mission
was a success.
It was a success
because the
Jem'Hadar security
slipped up
and we got lucky.
Don't use
those men again
for anything other than
routine reconnaissance.
They're five
of my best men.
Bronok is one
of the most experienced...
You've been told
before-- no names.
Each cell has
to be insulated
from the cell above
and the cell below.
If I know the
names of your men
and I am captured...
Yes, I've heard
the lecture.
Well, then you shouldn't
have to be reminded.
It's been a long day.
Why don't
we take a break?
Good idea.
The air in here
is getting stale.
( Garak chuckles )
You going to do
something about him?
I am.
I'm giving him my support.
All right.
This does not bode well.
Odo.
The raid on the Tevak
shipyard was successful.
I penetrated
the Operations Center
disabled
the security protocols.
The rest of the team
sabotaged
the dilithium
storage bunkers.
An hour after we left, the
entire facility was vaporized.
You should get some rest.
That sounds good to me.
Anyone in the
bunk room?
No.
Okay, it's
all yours.
Right.
Odo.
Good work.
Thank you.
( breathing heavily )
Huh?
It's just like you
to come sneaking in here
without warning.
My approach may have been quiet,
but I assure you
I had no intention
of sneaking up on you.
My apologies.
If... I may ask...
Why...
have I deteriorated
so rapidly?
( groans )
I've been assuming
dozens of different forms
over the... past few weeks.
Changing shape seems to...
accelerate the progress
of the disease.
Perhaps you should stop.
And do what?
Lie here waiting to die?
I came to work.
Work is what I'm going to do.
I take it Commander Kira is
unaware of your true condition.
That's right.
And I prefer
that it stays that way.
I won't breathe a word.
See that you don't.
She has enough
on her mind without...
worrying about me.
And I...
don't want... her...
Pity?
( sighs )
Is there a reason
you came in here?
We have need of a contact
on Kelvas V.
I remember your telling
me that you knew...
I may have a few names for you.
I have to give it some thought.
( breathes heavily )
Odo, I hope you know
how much I...
If I don't want pity
from the woman I love
why would I want it from you?
( sighs )
Morning.
Oh. What time is it?
0630.
Another all-nighter.
That's four in a row.
You can't keep this up.
I'm beginning
to agree with you.
And, to add insult to injury,
I'm not getting anywhere.
My DNA integration theory's
a blind alley.
So where does that leave you?
Back on square one.
Whoever engineered
this shape-shifter virus
certainly did a good job
of covering their tracks.
Julian, it's time to face facts.
You're not going
to pull a rabbit
out of your medkit.
Now, even the Founders
themselves couldn't find a cure
and they had all the resources
of the Dominion
at their command.
Now, I know you don't
want to hear this...
but the only way
we're going to find a cure
is to track down whoever created
this thing in the first place.
Miles...
We have got to find a way
to get inside Section 31.
We've tried that.
We've tried and we've tried
and all we managed to do
was waste two weeks
chasing phantoms
from here to Vulcan.
You want to face facts?
Face this fact:
Section 31 have managed
to stay in hiding
for over 300 years.
They're not going to come
scurrying into the light
just because Miles O'Brien
and Julian Bashir
are on the case.
Which is why I still say
we should take this
to Captain Sisko
and let him contact
Starfleet Intelligence.
Maybe they can...
All that will do
is alert Section 31
to the fact
that we're on to them.
And you know what they'll do?
They'll go deeper into hiding--
probably send
someone here
to destroy whatever
headway I've made.
No.
No more cloak and dagger games.
Science is the answer here.
Every puzzle has a solution,
every disease a cure.
It's just a matter
of finding it.
Now, if you'll kindly get
the hell out of here
I have work to do.
Martok's attack on Avenal VII
was a disgrace.
He had the advantage
of surprise.
The Dominion wasn't expecting us
to take the offensive
so soon after the Breen
entered the war.
Avenal should've been
an easy victory for him
but instead, he's handed
us a shameful defeat.
General Martok and I
both advised you
against attacking a world
so deep inside
Dominion territory.
He was outnumbered
six-to-one at Avenal.
Six-to-one.
A good Commander finds ways
to beat the odds
not hide behind them.
He didn't hide behind anything.
He fought longer and harder
than I would have in his place.
Have you read Worf's
after-action report?
( tossing padd on desk )
Seven Klingon ships
destroyed.
Five others severely damaged.
General Martok himself
in critical condition
in the Rotarran Sick Bay.
He's expected to survive.
That's not the point!
This entire operation has been
a waste of resources,
men and equipment.
The blame lies with the man
who ordered the mission
in the first place
not the man who tried
to carry it out.
That's one of the things
I like about you, Captain...
your loyalty to your friends.
This has nothing to do
with loyalty.
Of course not.
In any case,
you needn't worry.
Martok's a popular
General with the troops
and that counts
for something.
I won't relieve
him of command...
yet.
As you can see, the Klingon raid
on Avenal was easily broken up.
I am less concerned
about this Klingon attack
than I am
the Cardassian rebellion.
We cannot fight
the combined forces
of the Federation, the Klingons
and the Romulans
and face a full-scale uprising
behind the lines.
I completely agree.
However, the situation
is well in hand.
We still have control
over the Cardassian military
while Damar has only a handful
of terrorists at his disposal.
I assure you both
that this rebellion
poses no threat.
( electronically
distorted voice )
You are correct,
and you also assured us
that Damar would never turn
against the Dominion.
That was...
an error, to be sure,
but an understandable one.
No one could have foreseen
that Damar would become
a terrorist.
The concept is
antithetical to
the very nature
of Cardassians.
They respect authority.
They value the rule of law
and the security of order
which is exactly
what the Dominion offers them.
( distorted voice )
Exactly.
If our cloning facilities
were operational
I would eliminate
this Weyoun immediately.
Damar must pay
the price for his treason.
Redouble your efforts
to find his wife and children
and I want you to begin
interrogating Cardassian
teachers, scientists,
local officials.
The population must understand,
in no uncertain terms
that dissent
will not be tolerated.
Then I want you to begin
putting Cardassian civilians
in and around
the Dominion
military installations.
If Damar destroys another
shipyard, he will have to kill
a great many
of his own countrymen as well.
This will help turn the people
against him.
An excellent plan.
Your opinion was not solicited.
Thot Pran,
the sooner we can regain
the offensive on the front
lines, the better.
The installation of the Breen
weapons on the Dominion ships
must be accelerated.
Please issue the appropriate
orders to your engineers.
( distorted voice )
( sighs )
How long before
our cloning facilities
are operational again?
Not for several days,
perhaps even weeks.
Ah.
Well, keep me informed.
GARAK:
And according to our new
contact on Kelvas V
the Breen will
begin to install
their energy-dampening
weapons
aboard Jem'Hadar
fighters within a week.
Has the Federation
made any progress
in counteracting
these weapons?
No. They're
still having trouble
understanding
the underlying technology.
Well, why aren't
the Klingon ships
affected by these
Breen weapons?
We don't know
that yet either
but if we could supply
the Federation with one
it would give
them a chance
to come up with
a countermeasure.
I had the
same thought.
Our priority
should be to
free Cardassia
from the Dominion,
not do Starfleet's dirty work.
We're all in this together.
By helping Starfleet,
we're helping ourselves.
KIRA:
There's a Cardassian
repair facility
in the Kelvas system, right?
Yes.
I take it you have
something in mind.
It won't be easy, but...
if we can get onto the Bridge...
All right, we'll take
a five-man team--
the four of us plus Odo.
Garak, I'm going to need
everything you have
on the Kelvas facility.
Is something wrong?
Possibly.
Uh, may I have a few words
with the Commander?
What's on your mind?
It's about taking Odo
on this mission.
I'm afraid there's no easy way
of putting it.
He's been hiding the true extent
of his illness
from you
for some time now.
His condition has
severely deteriorated
and the more
he changes form...
the worse he gets.
I know.
You do?
I love him, Garak.
You think I really
wouldn't notice?
Why the pretense?
Because I also know
that he doesn't want me
to find out about it.
He wants to put
up a brave front
and protect me from
the truth, well, fine.
If that's what makes
this easier for him
if that gives him
one last shred
of dignity to hold onto
then I'll go on ignoring
what's happening to him
until the very end.
Anything else?
No.
All right.
We will need
a Cardassian shuttle
with the latest
security protocols.
And a schematic of the...
( on com )
Sisko to Worf.
Worf here.
SISKO: I'd like to see you
in my office, Commander.
On my way.
How's Martok?
Dr. Bashir says
he will make a full recovery.
I'm glad to hear that.
Mr. Worf, we've got
a serious problem
on our hands.
Gowron.
He seems
hell-bent
on continuing these offensives
regardless of the cost.
He is a stubborn
and arrogant man.
That may be true,
but I hope he's not a fool.
He's risking
the entire defense posture.
Why can't he see that?
I suspect the Chancellor cannot
see anything at the moment
except for one man.
You mean, Martok?
The Chancellor sees him
as a political threat.
These attacks
against the Dominion
are designed
to humiliate the General
in the eyes of the Empire--
to force him to endure
defeat after defeat.
Are you telling me that this
is a political vendetta?
It would not be the first time
that a Klingon Chancellor
put his own interests
ahead of the greater good.
Something has to be done.
Agreed.
And I do have a solution,
but it will not be easy.
You do whatever it takes,
Mr. Worf.
Those Klingon ships out there
are the only thing
between us and the Breen.
Gowron is risking the safety
of the entire Alpha Quadrant
and he has to stop.
Understood.
My men have secured
the shuttle.
They'll meet us
at those coordinates.
Good.
Are you enjoying yourself?
Getting Cardassians
to do your bidding
must give you great pleasure.
I'm a little busy right now,
Rusot.
Why don't you find
someone else to play with?
You may have fooled Damar
into believing you're here
to fight the Dominion
but I know
why you're really here.
Oh, this should be good.
You killed hundreds
of Cardassians
during the occupation
and now you're getting
a chance to do it again.
That's why you're here,
isn't it?
To hang a few more Cardassian
neck bones from your belt?
Admit it, Kira.
You won't be satisfied
until every one of us is dead.
Oh, I don't have time...
Don't you ever
touch me again.
I guess...
I hit a nerve.
No.
This is hitting
a nerve.
( groaning )
Stop pushing me or
I'll make you realize
just how many
nerves you have
in that miserable body.
( grunts )
When this is all over...
and the Dominion is defeated...
You won't have any trouble
finding me.
GARAK:
Oh, you'll have to do
something about him
long before that, Commander.
Thanks for all your help.
Oh, you seemed to have things
well under control.
Did I?
Despite his statement
to the contrary
Rusot will not wait
until the end of the war to make
his move.
I suggest
you don't wait either.
Kill him...
before he kills you.
Challenge Gowron
in the middle of a war?
It's treasonous.
Gowron is leading us all
to ruin.
It is your duty
to challenge him
to protect the Empire.
You would have me
protect the Empire
by breaking my oath...
by spilling the blood
of a Klingon brother
while an enemy
stands at our door?
Where is the honor in that?
He is sacrificing our troops
for his own petty reasons.
Where is the honor in that?
The troops are his to command.
It is not our place
to question him unless
he is acting with cowardice
and there is no proof of that.
You are not listening.
I have heard every word
that you have said.
You want me
to become Chancellor.
Me.
( chuckles )
Tell me, Worf.
How do you think the members
of the High Council will react
when they're asked to follow
a common man
from the Ketha lowlands?
A man without a drop
of noble blood in his veins?
Kahless himself
was not highborn.
Kahless was divine.
Your name
is revered
throughout the Empire.
If you seize the leadership
every warrior
from here to Kronos
would swear an oath to you,
and with that kind of support
the High Council
will have no choice
but to accept you as Chancellor.
You begin to sound
like a Romulan.
You know I am right.
( sighs )
I am a loyal soldier
of the Empire.
I would rather die
than dishonor my uniform.
By raising a hand
to my Chancellor
in a time of war,
I would bring
shame to everything
that I've fought to protect
everything that I believe in.
General.
My decision is made!
We will not speak of this again.
You're staring again.
Sorry.
I'm... I'm just
worried about you.
Well, don't.
It may be a long time before
the symptoms manifest themselves
and, by then, I'm sure Dr.
Bashir will have found the cure.
Right.
Uh, could you take the helm?
I'm going to get
a raktajino.
What's wrong?
One of our listening posts
picked up a message.
The Dominion has succeeded
in locating Damar's family.
They're dead.
They weren't a part
of this rebellion.
The Dominion knew that.
The Founder knew that.
Weyoun
knew that.
To kill her and my son...
the casual brutality of it...
the waste of life.
What kind of state
tolerates the murder
of innocent women and children?
What kind of people
give those orders?
Yeah, Damar, what kind of people
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
Oh, that was stupid.
Not at all.
Damar has a certain...
romanticism about the past.
He could use
a dose of cold water.
Well, I could've picked
a better time.
If he's the man
to lead a new Cardassia
if he's the man
we all hope him to be
then the pain of this news
made him more receptive
to what you said, not less.
( console beeping )
We're approaching
the rendezvous point.
The shuttle is here.
Right on time,
just as I promised.
Damar to Shuttle.
Lower your shields
and we'll beam aboard.
MALE:
Acknowledged.
Let's go.
...and, in truth,
I understand
his position.
It is the duty
of every soldier
to support their leaders
in time of war.
Asking Martok to
stand against Gowron
was a foolish error.
So what are you going to do?
Try to convince Gowron to
discontinue these attacks.
You have said
very little.
Look...
I'm just not sure that I
should be giving you advice
on what to do in this situation.
It's a Klingon matter.
You are still a member
of the House of Martok.
This is the first
that I've heard of it.
The General and I
talked about it
weeks ago.
He likes you
and he considers you
an honorable woman--
a worthy successor
to Jadzia.
And so do I.
That's very sweet of him.
Sweet?
Not a very Klingon word, is it?
No.
It's very... honorable.
Better.
Albeit, a little obvious.
Now...
tell me what
you think.
Okay, but I'm not sure
you're going to like it.
Tell me.
I think that the situation
with Gowron
is a symptom
of a bigger problem.
The Klingon Empire is dying
and I think
it deserves to die.
You were right.
I do not like it.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm very touched
that you still consider me
to be a member
of the House of Martok
but... I tend to look
at the Empire
with a little more skepticism
than Curzon or Jadzia did.
I see a society that is
in deep denial about itself.
We're talking
about a warrior culture
that prides itself
on maintaining
centuries-old traditions
of honor and integrity
but, in reality,
it's willing
to accept corruption
at the highest levels.
You are overstating your case.
Am I?
Who was the last leader of the
High Council that you respected?
Has there
even been one?
And how many times
have you had to cover up
the crimes of Klingon leaders
because you were told that it
was for the good of the Empire?
I... I know this sounds harsh,
but the truth is
you have been willing
to accept a government
that you know is corrupt.
Gowron is just
the latest example.
Worf
you are the most honorable
and decent man
that I have ever met
and if you are willing
to tolerate men like Gowron
then what hope is there
for the Empire?
We have a prisoner
for the Vorta
who commands this ship.
Everything seems
to be in order
but you'll have to
leave your weapons here.
Why?
New orders from
Dominion Headquarters--
no armed Cardassians allowed
aboard Jem'Hadar vessels.
It sounds like they don't
trust us anymore.
So it would seem.
I'm sorry, but those
are the orders.
Well, it's not your fault.
Do as he says.
The three of us should be able
to handle one Bajoran woman.
Take them
to the Bridge.
Good luck...
Legate Damar.
( hatch closes )
We'll run the first test firing
in two hours, 14 minutes.
Agreed.
Coordinate it
with Central Operations.
What's this?
We have a prisoner.
I can see that.
Why are you
bringing her to me?
This is Commander Rota
the Deputy
Intelligence Officer
for this entire sector.
I would think that
you'd be interested
in interrogating her.
I wasn't informed of this.
Perhaps you haven't
received the report yet.
It's not surprising.
We only took
the Commander
prisoner yesterday.
We were under
a communications blackout...
Let me see your orders.
Of course.
Founder.
You honor us with your presence.
I... had no idea
you were in this sector.
My movements are
none of your concern.
No.
Have you begun the interrogation
of this prisoner?
Not yet.
Good.
I will conduct
the questioning myself.
As you wish.
Ah... I see
the upgraded plasma rifles
have been distributed.
May I inspect it?
Aha.
An excellent weapon.
What do you think?
Secure
those hatches.
It wasn't necessary
to kill them all.
We can't afford to be
burdened by prisoners.
We'll argue about this later.
Prepare to flood all decks below
the Bridge with neurazine gas.
Bring the warp drive on line.
Lay in a course
for the Federation.
Commander.
They haven't
finished installing
the Breen weapon.
We can't leave.
How long before they finish
installing the weapon?
We can't wait!
I'm not leaving
without that weapon.
GARAK:
There are three...
no, four Breen working
in the engine room.
Judging from the diagnostics,
I'd say it'll take them
30 to 45 minutes
to complete their work.
We don't have that much time.
Yes, we do.
No one even knows
we're on the Bridge.
All we have to do is sit tight
give the standard replies
to any inquiries
and wait for the Breen to do
their work.
Damar, this is insane.
She'll get us all killed.
There's an incoming message.
They want to speak
to the Vorta.
( sighs )
Disable the visual feed.
What was her name?
Come on!
I'm looking.
Ah. Her name was Luaran.
This is Luaran.
No, I can't see you either.
We're experiencing trouble
with our com system.
What do you want?
Just a moment.
They want
the status report on
our navigational array.
I've got it.
That data is coming to you.
Excellent.
We'll be repairing
our com system
for at least the next hour.
I'll contact you
when we're finished.
Luaran out.
What if they didn't believe you?
Then we're dead.
( sighs )
Hey.
Keiko whipped you
up some crab rolls.
She... well, we thought
you might be hungry.
Thanks...
uh, to both of you.
Uh, about the other day...
Oh, forget it.
How's the work going?
I'm still firmly entrenched
in square one.
You mind
if I ask you a question?
About 31?
Go ahead.
Well, if you were
to find the cure
and they got to know about it...
what do you think they'd do?
Well, I imagine they'd be, uh...
very concerned.
The very existence
of a cure
would jeopardize their plan
to eradicate the Founders.
Wouldn't surprise me
if Sloan or another operative
turned up here on the station
to destroy my work.
What are you getting at?
I think you should send
a message to Starfleet Medical
saying that you have found
the cure.
You're trying to lure someone
from Section 31?
Yeah. That's right.
What happens when this operative
gets here?
We capture him.
Then we figure out a way
to get some information
out of him.
He may not know anything
about the disease.
Maybe not...
but I bet he knows who does.
What do you think?
I think it's a plan...
a very good plan.
When did you get
so devious?
I've been hanging around you
too long.
Let's just hope
this works
and we cure Odo.
That's all I care about.
Me, too, Miles.
GOWRON:
Our next target...
Sarpedion V.
Sarpedion is the headquarters
of the entire 12th Order.
Yes. You'll take 15
Vor'cha-class battle cruisers
in first
to soften their defenses.
Then, General Chu'vok, you'll...
Chancellor!
That world is one of the most
heavily fortified positions
in the entire Cardassian Empire.
15 battle cruisers
will barely
scratch their defenses.
( chuckles )
If you lack the courage
to fight an uphill battle
then perhaps you should
retire to your bed.
I will fight any battle...
anywhere.
For the Empire.
Spoken like a true warrior.
After Martok has softened
their defenses...
No.
We cannot attack Sarpedion.
I decide what can...
and cannot be done.
You rule without wisdom
and without honor.
The warriors that
are gathered here
would not say this
to you, but I will.
You are squandering our ships
and our lives
on a petty act of vengeance!
I should've known better
than to trust you again.
If you were
a true Klingon
I would kill you
where you stand!
Fortunately for you
that... child's uniform shields
you from your rightful fate.
What I say now
I say as a member of
the House of Martok
not a Starfleet officer.
You have dishonored yourself
and the Empire, and
you are not worthy
to lead the Council.
There can be only one answer
to that.
Worf...
this is madness.
( growling )
( grunting )
( screaming )
( yelling )
You will not have this... day.
( roaring )
Hail Worf!
Leader of the Empire.
Worf!
( all chanting ):
Worf! Worf! Worf!
Worf! Worf!
Wait.
Worf!
Hear me. Hear me!
Worf... !
What I have done...
was for the Empire.
A new day must dawn
for our people.
I am not the man
to usher in that day
but there is a man here who can.
Worf...
I do not seek the leadership.
Kahless said, "Great
men do not seek power.
They have power
thrust upon them."
Hail Martok!
Leader of the Empire.
Leader of destiny.
How much longer?
I'm not certain.
It appears
they're having problems
connecting the secondary relays.
( grunts )
Odo, are you all right?
Yes.
Don't worry. I'm...
( groaning )
I'm... I'm sorry.
There's nothing
to be sorry about.
( groans )
Just... stay
with me, Odo.
Stay with me.
We're going to get out of here.
All right? Just hang on
a little while longer.
RUSOT:
It's over.
Shut up, Rusot.
The shape-shifter
is useless.
The whole plan
is coming apart.
We have to get
out of here now.
Go back to
your post.
No. No more.
We're leaving now.
That would be unwise.
You're still a Cardassian,
Garak.
You're not going to kill
one of your own people
for a Bajoran woman.
How little
you understand me.
Put your weapons
down, both of you!
You want her dead,
too, Damar.
I know you do.
But you're the leader
of the rebellion
and don't want to kill someone
wearing a Starfleet uniform.
Let me do it for you.
( beeping )
They've finished installing
the dampening weapon.
Then let's all get
the hell out of here.
Not you.
I'm still here, Rusot.
Damar, shoot him.
We can kill them both and keep
the Breen weapon for ourselves.
I believe in you, Damar.
I know you're the right man
to restore the Empire
we so loyally served
the Empire we loved.
Together, we can
lead our people
to greatness again.
Just aim and fire.
( groaning, loud thud )
He was my friend...
( sighing )
but his Cardassia is dead
and it won't be coming back.
Flood all compartments
with the gas.
Clear all moorings.
Bow thrusters ahead full.
We've cleared
their defense perimeter.
( breathing heavily )
Take the helm.
You're... probably angry.
Why?
I...
I hid my true condition.
Odo... I've known all along.
But it's not over.
Julian's probably working
on a cure right now.
Shh, shh. Nerys,
Nerys, don't.
Just...
stay here... with me.