Chief Medical Officer's Log,
Stardate 52645.7.
Colonel Kira, Garak and Odo
have returned to the station.
Despite my best efforts,
I have yet to make any progress
toward finding a cure
for Odo's disease.
How long do I have?
I can't be sure.
You can make an educated guess.
I could, but first, I'd like
to talk about slowing down
the progress of the disease
with a series
of nadion bursts.
I want a time frame, Doctor.
A week... maybe two
with the
nadion therapy.
Thank you.
Now I want to see Kira.
Let me emphasize, Odo,
that I haven't given up hope
and it's very important
that you don't
give up, either.
Understood.
Now, please...
let me see Kira.
How do you feel?
Better.
This contraption of Julian's
seems to alleviate the pain.
Good.
You should be going soon.
I'm not going anywhere.
Damar and Garak can lead
the rebellion without me.
Damar needs someone
who's actually fought
with a resistance movement.
That's you, not Garak.
I am not leaving
until I know that you're...
I want... you... to leave.
Why?
You... watched Bareil die
in this very room.
I know how that's
haunted you.
I don't want
your last memory of me
to be witnessing my death.
Isn't that my choice?
Maybe it is...
and maybe I'm being selfish
telling you
all the things I want
but I don't want...
the last thing I see...
to be... pain in your eyes.
You'd be surprised how well
I can hide my feelings...
when I need to.
Not from me.
You have to go, Nerys.
( softly ):
All right.
Uh...
I-I can't be
a very pleasant sight.
I don't care how you look.
I've got so much to say, I...
I don't know where to begin.
Just say you love me.
That's all
I've ever cared about.
I love you, Odo.
I love you, Nerys.
O'BRIEN:
After I finished the tests
I forwarded the schematics
of the Breen weapon
to Starfleet Engineering.
They should have
a preliminary repor...
Garak and I should
be getting underway.
The Commander
is correct.
We have to evade several
Jem'Hadar patrols
in order to reach
Damar's base.
If we wait too long
they may alter
their patrol routes.
Chief... is there anything else
before they go?
No, sir. I think we have
all the data we need.
Well, then.
Good hunting to you both.
Thank you, sir.
Julian...
I'll do
everything I can.
Doctor?
Is there anything
I can do to help?
Any additional resources
you might want
from Starfleet Medical?
No, thank you, sir.
I think I have
everything I need.
Sir, we should inform you
that research
is not the only avenue
we've been pursuing.
( softly ):
Miles!
He needs to know.
Whatever's going on,
I want to know it right now.
We're... trying to lure
someone from Section 31
here to the station.
Section 31?
What do they have
to do with this?
We believe that
they were responsible
for infecting Odo
in the first place.
What?
We believe that he became
infected three years ago
when he underwent
a medical examination
at Starfleet
Headquarters.
O'BRIEN:
Evidently,
Section 31 hoped
that Odo would
transmit the disease
to the other Founders
when he linked with them.
Genocide...
committed by people who call
themselves Federation citizens.
Why didn't you come to me
earlier with this?
Sir, we felt that...
Miles wanted to
tell you, sir
but I ordered
him not to.
It's my fault.
I'm still waiting for an answer
to my question.
We have no proof.
Besides, I knew that if we
told you what we suspected
you'd feel obliged to inform
Starfleet Command,
and once you did that
Section 31
would realize
that we were on to them,
and go even deeper into hiding.
What difference did that make?
There came a point
when I had to admit
that my research
was going nowhere.
I couldn't find a cure
here in the lab.
So Miles and I decided
to look for one within
Section 31 itself.
So a few days ago,
I sent a false message
to Starfleet Medical
informing them that I had,
indeed, found a cure.
The idea is that when
Section 31 hears about it
they'll want to destroy
Julian's research
in order to prevent it falling
into the hands of the Dominion.
So you're trying to lure
one of their operatives
to the station.
Okay.
Let's say it works.
What then?
We capture him or her,
find out everything
they know about the disease,
who's involved
and maybe even where
to find the cure.
How do you propose to do that?
They're not going to be
very cooperative.
I, uh, managed
to get my hands
on a Romulan
memory scanner, sir.
( whispers ):
Oh...
Since they're illegal
in the Federation
I'll assume that's another
reason you didn't come to me.
Yes, sir.
Well... setting aside
all the legal
and ethical issues involved...
I still think
this is a pretty long shot.
I do, too
but I'm afraid
it's the only shot Odo has.
Can't sleep?
No.
How'd you get in?
The lock isn't that complex.
What are you doing up?
Oh, I was running
another power test
on the Breen weapon.
I was trying
to read
and I kept reading
the same page
over and over again.
What were you reading?
"It was the best of times,
it was the worst of times..."
A Tale of Two Cities--
my mother's favorite book.
I was enjoying it, too
except tonight...
my mind was elsewhere.
Odo?
Section 31.
I kept thinking
just how many people had
to have been involved
in the conspiracy
to infect him
with the disease--
computer experts, doctors,
security officers
admirals... clerks.
In the end, I came up
with at least 73 people.
For a minute there
I thought you were going
to say 70,000.
This...
organization...
this...
thing...
that slithered its way
into the heart
of the Federation...
it has to be destroyed.
Well, you won't get any argument
from me on that...
but for now,
the focus has to be Odo
finding him a cure.
That has to be our priority.
You're right.
I've had enough.
Have you?
Sure.
Let's sleep lightly tonight.
Section 31 may still fall
for the trap and show.
I'll be ready.
Lights.
Hello, Doctor.
I didn't think
I'd ever see you again.
I have another assignment
for you.
Really?
What a coincidence...
because I have an assignment
for you.
I take it I'm supposed
to feel shocked and humbled
by your ingenuity.
Frankly,
I don't care how you feel.
Bashir to O'Brien.
O'BRIEN ( on com ):
Yeah?
Mr. Sloan is here.
I have him
in the containment field.
O'BRIEN:
I'm on my way.
Good.
Bashir out.
What do you want, Doctor?
Why, the same thing you want--
the cure... to Odo's disease.
What are you talking about?
You already have the cure.
No...
no, you don't.
Your message to Starfleet
Medical was just bait.
Which I'm happy to see
you swallowed.
( laughing )
Well...
you've got me.
What good do you think is going
to come of this?
Turning me over
to Starfleet Security
would be a waste of time.
You don't have a shred
of evidence.
Oh, I'm not interested
in turning you over...
to anyone.
Wel...
( grunts )
Hello again.
Shooting an unarmed man--
that's a little ungallant,
isn't it?
Somehow, I didn't expect you
to come here
of your own volition.
Oh, you're probably right.
Hello, Chief.
How's the family?
Everyone okay
at home?
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
I'd just hate
to see anything happen to them.
BASHIR:
Don't listen
to him, Chief.
He's just playing games
with you.
That's easy for him to say.
He doesn't have a wife
and children to worry about
but trust me, Chief--
if something were
to happen to me...
What?
They'd be killed?
I'm disappointed in you, Sloan.
You don't usually wield
such a blunt instrument.
( chuckles )
So... am I supposed to guess
what's going on
or do I have
to lay here in terror
waiting for you to tell me?
I told you what's going on.
I'm going to find a cure
for Odo's disease
and you're going to help me.
What makes you think
I know anything about it?
You came here
because you thought
I had discovered a cure
and you wanted
to destroy it
but, first, you'd have
to find it in my lab
and in order to do that,
you'd have to know
exactly what it was
you were looking for.
( chuckling )
You call that reasoning?
If I wanted
to eliminate your work
all I'd have to do
is destroy your lab.
Oh, no, no, no, Sloan.
That would be too sloppy.
You like surgical precision.
You came here
to destroy the cure.
So, somewhere
in that brain of yours
is the information that I want.
You really expect me
to tell you?
No.
I expect you to resist
to the bitter end.
We're ready.
Remember these?
Romulan mind probes.
They're not
the most pleasant of devices
but they're very efficient.
They're also illegal
in the Federation.
Oh, I hope you can appreciate
the irony of that statement.
I'm telling you
I don't know anything
about the cure.
Then I won't find anything,
will I?
If Sisko finds out
what you're do...
The Captain already knows
what we're doing.
We have his full support.
Julian...
I'm sorry about Odo
but I can't let you have
the cure.
I can't take a chance it'll fall
into the hands of the Founders.
I'm afraid the choice is
no longer yours, Sloan.
I misread you.
I thought you were
just a misguided idealist
but you're a dangerous man.
People like you
would destroy the Federation
if given a chance.
Fortunately,
there are people like me
who will die to protect it.
( grunting )
Damn!
What's going on?
He's trying to kill himself.
He's activated
a neuro-depolarizing
device in his brain.
I have to stabilize him
before he does
irreversible damage.
If he dies...
The cure for Odo
dies with him!
( console beeping )
O'BRIEN:
What's the verdict?
Well, he's stable for now
but the neuro-depolarizer
did damage his brain.
Even on full life support,
his higher cortical functions
will fail within
the next hour.
He committed suicide...
just to prevent us
finding the cure.
We had him cornered
and he knew it.
He just couldn't let
one of Section 31's
darkest secrets
get away from him.
The frustrating
thing is
the cure's still
in there somewhere.
Julian, this might sound
a bit morbid, but...
what if you were to use your
Romulan mental probes now?
His memory pathways
have been scrambled--
probably to prevent someone
from doing just that.
There must be some way
to retrieve that data.
Well, maybe we should just
let him die in peace.
Miles...
I need a multitronic
engrammatic interpreter.
Or maybe I'll find you
a multitronic engrammatic
interpreter.
This is crazy.
Oh, it'll work.
You have me rerouting so many
power relays and transfer coils
I can't guarantee
any of this will work
without running
a series of diagnostics.
I've already done
the diagnostics, Miles
in my head.
The neural interface
will then provide
a basic pattern to
my hippocampal nuclei.
( frustrated sigh )
I give up.
You've explained it
to me three times
and I still don't get it.
You just have to
trust me, Chief.
I know what I'm doing.
But, now even if you can
link minds with Sloan
how are you going
to find the cure?
The entire experience
will be processed
into images and sounds
that my conscious mind
can comprehend.
In essence, I will see
the neuronal pathways
in Sloan's brain
as literal pathways...
or streets or corridors
or something.
Oh, so you're
just going to...
wander around
these streets
looking for a little box
labeled "The Cure."
As strange as it sounds,
it may be just that simple
or it may be a good deal
more surrealistic.
I may wind up in memories
of Sloan's childhood.
Will he be...
you know, aware of
what you're doing?
I won't know that
till I'm in there.
We don't know what
the conscious mind
can perceive
this close to
brain death.
How will you get out?
One of the advantages
of being genetically-enhanced
is the ability to control
my own vital signs.
When I find a cure
and I want to get out
I'll send my hypothalamus
a signal
to raise my blood
pressure 40 percent
and the equipment will
automatically break the link.
What if you get disoriented,
or...
lost in some nightmare
of Sloan's
and he dies while
you're still in there?
Worst-case scenario--
I die with him, I suppose
but I think
that's a manageable risk.
I'm going with you.
What?
You heard me.
And it's not open to debate.
If you're determined to go
on this lunatic mission
inside Sloan's head
then somebody with an ounce
of sanity has to be with you.
You just want to come
because you don't want
Captain Sisko to find
out what we're doing.
Well, there's that, too.
I better get another bed.
How long have we got?
Sloan's brain's going to die
in about 43 minutes.
We have that long to get in,
find the cure...
and get out.
The analyzer's on line.
Are you ready?
No...
but let's do it anyway.
Jules?
Miles.
Why are we in a turbolift?
I'm not sure.
I don't remember
getting in here.
We're in Sloan's mind...
remember?
Sloan.
But we're really still...
in the lab.
Yes.
This turbolift
is just an abstraction.
Then where are we going?
I don't know...
( speed increases rapidly )
but we're not wasting any time
getting there.
Aren't you glad
you came along?
Oh, I wouldn't have
missed it for the world.
( turbolift slows and stops )
So, what do you think?
I think we stopped.
Are you sure?
Either that, or we're falling
very, very slowly.
You mean we can let go?
I don't see why not.
Well?
Well, what?
You first.
Oh, no.
This little trip wasn't my idea.
All right.
We'll let go together.
On the count of three.
One...
two...
three.
See?
Nothing to worry about.
I wasn't worried.
( dropping with a loud crash)
What now?
Good question.
Doctor, Chief O'Brien.
Welcome.
I can't tell you
how happy I am to see you.
Well, we're glad
you're happy, Sloan.
Now, tell us how to cure Odo
and we can all be happy.
Believe me, Doctor
nothing would give
me greater pleasure
but first, there
are a few people
I'd like you to meet.
Look, Sloan, we're a
bit pressed for time.
But you just arrived.
Oh... I see.
You're afraid that if I die
while you're still in here
you'll die, too.
Yes... well, we can't let
that happen, can we?
We'd better hurry.
We're not going anywhere
till you give us the cure.
All right.
If you insist.
It... it's a simple nucleotide
marking sequence.
Radodine...
( slightly garbled ):
uh, lidestolinine...
( electronically
garbled voice )
Would you mind repeating that?
( electronically
garbled voice )
We're not playing
games, Sloan!
Believe me, I want to tell you
what you need to know.
Then tell us.
I can't.
( electronically
garbled voice )
Do you see?
I suppose there's
some part of me
that doesn't
want you to know.
Well, not until you come
to the Wardroom.
Maybe we should do as he says.
I don't blame you
for being suspicious
but if you want the cure
you're going
to have to trust me...
and the clock is ticking.
He's right about that.
Follow me.
Relax, Doctor.
I'm the one who's dying,
not you.
Why Deep Space 9?
Excuse me?
I'm just wondering why
the inside of your head
looks like our
space station.
I wanted you to feel at home,
comfortable.
Why?
I thought it was
the decent thing to do.
Everyone...
if I could have your
attention, please.
Now that we're all here,
I hope you'll forgive me
if I take a moment
and say a few words.
As I stand here...
reunited with my friends
and my family
for one last time,
I want you
the people I love,
to know just how sorry I am
for all the pain
that I've caused you.
I dedicated my life
to the preservation
and the protection
of the Federation.
This duty, which I carried out
to the best of my ability
took precedence over
everything else--
my parents, my wife,
my children.
I lived in a world of secrets...
of sabotage
and deceit.
I spent so
much time...
erasing my
movements
covering
my tracks
that now, as I look back
on my life...
I find nothing.
It's as if I never
really existed.
I cheated you all
out of being in my life...
and what's more,
I cheated myself, as well.
Now, I know a simple apology
won't change that.
Still, I feel the need
to apologize anyway.
No tears, please.
My death isn't
a tragedy
it's a celebration.
In death, I can finally
step out of the shadows
and prove to myself
that I existed...
that I lived.
( applause )
That was beautiful, Luther.
Gentlemen...
I'd like you to meet
my wife, Jessica.
This is Dr. Bashir,
Chief O'Brien.
If it weren't for them,
I wouldn't be here.
I'd like to thank you for
all you've done for Luther
and me.
Frankly, being married
to him was a living hell...
but thanks to you
that's all changed.
Well, congratulations.
Doctor, you've been
a beacon of light to me.
You're living proof
that ideology
is a poor substitute
for kindness and decency
and that at the end of the day,
it's our actions
and not our beliefs
that define
who we are
what we are.
Yes... I mean, thank you.
I'm... I'm very glad
to have been helpful.
Um... but if
you don't mind...
You want me to tell you
how to cure Odo.
Gladly, Doctor.
My dear, I need that padd
I gave you for safekeeping.
Oh, yes, I think
I have it here.
Thanks, muffin.
Here you go, Doctor.
( Jessica screaming )
I'm sorry, Doctor
but I can't let you have that.
Julian...
Don't look at me
for explanations.
I knew it.
Knew what?
That this wasn't
going to be easy.
( door opens )
SISKO:
Do you mind telling me
what's going on here?
I have no idea.
The Chief was
supposed to come
fix my sonic shower
this morning
but he never showed up.
I asked the computer
where he was
and when I came in,
this is what I found.
Have any idea
who this is?
Sloan. He works
for Section 31.
Then I guess this
isn't some kind
of obscure
meditation therapy.
Definitely not.
Sisko to Infirmary.
MALE ( on com ):
Infirmary.
Send a medical team
to Science Lab 4 right away.
Aye, sir.
I wish I knew how long
we've been in here.
23 minutes
and 11 seconds.
Show-off.
That leaves us
less than 20 minutes
to find a cure
and get out.
Locked-- all locked.
Sloan could be hiding
in any one of these rooms.
Or he could have taken
that turnoff we passed.
What's your point, Miles?
He's not going
to be found
unless he wants
to be found.
I mean, it's his
playing field.
MALE:
You two--
stop right there.
Now what?
You're in a restricted area.
I thought we were
in the cerebellum.
( sighing )
We're looking for Sloan.
Mr. Sloan's not available
at the moment.
Damn it, we-we don't
have time for this.
We need to speak
to Sloa...
( groaning )
You shot him!
That really hurt.
He was a threat
to the Federation.
Yeah?
( groaning )
You all right?
Do I look all right?
( both panting )
It doesn't make sense.
I mean, if none
of this is real
why does it hurt so much?
Well, Sloan's mind
must be sending
sensory stimuli
into ours
causing us to
experience pain--
just as we would had
we really been shot.
Of course, that's
just a theory.
Oh. Well, that makes sense.
Maybe this is a good time
for you to get us out of here.
I can't.
What do you mean,
you can't?
I just tried--
the hypothalamic
feedback loop.
I must be too weak.
What do you mean,
you're too weak?
Julian, we have
to get out of here!
I know that,
but I've been shot.
At least my body
thinks I have.
Well...
I don't believe this.
I'm sorry.
Well, so... this is it?
It does look that way.
Oh...
I should have left
a note for Keiko
to let her know
what we were planning.
Ah, why worry her?
No, I want her
and the kids
to understand why
I had to do this.
She'll understand.
She'll know.
You did it for me.
That's what'll upset her
the most.
She always said I...
I liked you more
than I liked her.
That-that-that's
ridiculous.
Right.
Well, maybe-maybe
you do...
a bit more.
What? Are you crazy?
She's my wife.
I love her.
Of course you love her.
She's your wife.
Yeah.
I'm just saying
maybe you like me a
bit more, that's all.
I do not.
You spend more
time with me.
We work together.
We have more in common.
Julian, you are
beginning to annoy me.
Darts, racquetball,
Vic's Lounge
the Alamo...
need I go on?
I love my wife.
And I love Ezri,
passionately.
You do?
Yes.
Have you told her?
Not yet...
but I will.
Oh, yeah? Ha!
When?
When I'm ready.
It's just that
I like you...
a bit more.
See, there,
I've admitted it.
Yeah, well...
I love my wife.
What's that?
O'BRIEN:
It's the tunnel.
What tunnel?
You know, the...
the tunnel
to the Great Beyond.
Oh... it is.
I must say, I'm
a bit disappointed.
I expected it
to be more elaborate.
No...
No, no, no.
Come on, come on, we ca...
we can't just sit here
waiting for... death.
Come on,
on your feet, man.
Come on, come on.
Let's check one more door.
What's the point?
The point is to do our duty
right up until the end.
Like Travis
and Crockett?
One more door.
WORF:
Dr. Bashir's
regaining consciousness,
Captain.
How's Miles?
I'm fine.
Did you find the information
you were looking for?
No, I'm afraid not.
I'm going to have
to go back in.
SISKO:
Sloan is dying.
We can't risk losing you
as well.
He can't die...
not yet.
Get me cordrazine,
ten milligrams.
His alpha waves are attenuating.
Cortical stimulator.
You're not getting away from me
that easily, Sloan.
( alarm beeping )
Increase the resonance
frequency ten percent.
NURSE:
His neurosynaptic activity
is falling.
I can see that!
50 milligrams neurotropan.
Come on, Sloan.
Come on back!
( steady tone sounds )
Complete neural failure.
No!
Doctor... he is dead.
Doctor...
It's over, Julian.
He's gone.
And so is any hope
of curing Odo.
I'm sorry, Odo.
I wish I had better news.
I understand, Doctor.
You've done
everything you could...
more than I would
have thought possible.
I appreciate it.
Is there anything I can do
to make you feel
more comfortable?
Thank you
but right now,
I'd simply like to be alone.
Of course.
How'd he take it?
( sighing )
You know, better
than I would've.
( sighing )
I need some sleep.
So do you.
Look, Julian...
No. I know.
I know. I did
all I could.
That is a small
comfort, isn't it?
"It was the best of times..."?
"It was the worst of times."
Well, it's the first
line of the book.
That's right.
So why is it there
on page 294?
Well, it must
be a misprint.
The book starts
over again.
It can't be--
Ezri loaned it to me
and before that,
it was Jadzia's
and I know for a fact
that she read it.
You and Ezri are
exchanging books?
Oh, forget about that.
Don't you see
what's going on?
Yeah, she's playing a
practical joke on you.
No, she isn't.
It's Sloan.
We're still inside his mind.
What are you
talking about?
These are my quarters.
Keiko's asleep
in that room.
No, she isn't.
Sloan's drawing
on our memories
making us think
we're back on the station.
That's why
the book's incomplete--
because I hadn't
finished reading it.
And because you don't
know what happens
after page 294...
He couldn't fill in
the rest of the story.
He's trying to stop us
finding the cure.
We must have been
close to finding it.
That door we were about to open
when we woke up...
the cure must be in there.
( deep rumbling )
What's happening?
Sloan's dying.
His mind's shutting down.
We haven't got much time.
( deep rumbling )
This is it.
Are you sure?
I can tell.
Sloan?
( rumbling )
Welcome to Section 31,
gentlemen.
You know exactly
why we're here.
You don't really expect me
to help you.
Are you sure
you want to throw
that one away?
I'm collecting
medical information
not surveillance reports.
That's not just any report.
That's on Jaresh-Inyo.
The former President Inyo?
The one and only.
My God...
31 had a man in his cabinet.
Don't let him distract you.
Just one of the little nuggets
lying around
in this once tidy room.
You'd be amazed
at what you could find.
Current operations on Kronos.
Chancellor Martok would love
to get his hands on this.
Julian...
look at this.
Radodine, lidestolinine,
asporanine, adenine.
That's it.
I think it's time
we got out of here.
Hold on a minute.
What for?
These files-- they contain
all of Sloan's memories
on Section 31.
With this information
we can destroy the
entire organization.
That'll have to wait!
It's not that simple, Chief.
There is no building
no room like this
in the real world.
Section 31 has
no headquarters.
These files...
they exist only in the minds
of a very select group of people
and I happen to be one of them.
If you really want to destroy
Section 31
it's now or never.
He's right.
This is a once-in-a-
lifetime opportunity.
We can't pass it up.
Julian!
What?!
Listen to me.
He wants us to die with him.
If we die, Odo dies, too.
SLOAN:
All my secrets
yours for the taking, Doctor...
if you want them badly enough.
Odo needs you, Julian.
He's counting on you.
You're making
a terrible mistake, Doctor.
I don't think so.
EZRI:
Julian?
Are you with us?
Ezri...
you look so... beautiful.
Did you locate
the cure?
I think so...
but there's only one way
to know for sure.
Sloan?
SISKO:
He died about
two minutes ago.
He almost took you with him.
Hey, Julian,
next time you take a trip
inside someone's mind,
you're going on your own.
Right.
I should warn you,
you may feel some discomfort.
If you mean
it's going to be painful
just say so.
It's going to be painful.
All right, then.
Go ahead.
( gasping )
( groaning )
( relieved sigh )
So, when will Odo
be up and around again?
Well, his
morphogenic matrix
needs a little
time to heal
but he should be
his old self
in a couple of days.
Aha!
Here we go.
I knew Quark was hoarding
a bottle of the good stuff.
This is older
than I am.
What?!
I'm drinking with a child.
( chuckles )
To aging... gracefully.
Very funny.
To Odo.
Wow.
Wow is right.
Tell me something.
If you'd had more time
to read the data
in Sloan's mind
do you think we would've
brought down Section 31?
Ah, we'll never
know now, will we?
But one thing's for sure--
Sloan knew he had
the perfect bait
that I wouldn't be
able to resist it
but there was one thing
he failed to consider.
And what's that?
You.
To Miles Edward O'Brien.
To friendship.
Oh.
Ah.
Well, I better get home.
Keiko is holding
dinner for me.
This late?
Yeah, well,
she's a hell of a woman.
That's why you love her.
Mmm, that's right.
That's why I love her.
You want to come?
Sure.