Anything yet?
Should be here any minute.
Running
a little late.
This is no way to start
a relationship.
Hi, Ezri.
So, how's Odo?
Oh, his body
shows no signs
of the changeling
disease.
I believe he's cured.
Oh, that's great.
Yes, in fact, um...
I'm going to discharge
him this afternoon.
That's... that's
really great.
Yeah.
I don't get it.
He's interested,
she's interested.
What's the problem?
He is an
overgrown child
and she is
very... confused.
It could still work.
( console beeping )
She's here.
On screen.
EZRI:
I didn't know we were
getting another
Defiant-class ship.
That's what happens
when you miss staff meetings.
Looks... just like her.
Let's hope she fights like her.
ROSS:
All hands, attention to orders.
From Starfleet Headquarters,
Office of the Admiralty
to Captain Benjamin L. Sisko.
As of this date,
you are requested and required
to take command
of USS Sao Paulo.
Signed, Vice Admiral William
J. Ross, Stardate 52861.3.
Computer, transfer
all command codes
to Captain Sisko.
Command codes transferred.
I relieve you, sir.
I stand relieved.
She's all yours, Ben.
You've a fine ship here.
She has some...
big shoes to fill.
I hate the carpet.
I do.
Oh, uh, by the way
there's, uh, something else
on that padd
that might interest you.
Special Dispensation
from the Chief
of Starfleet Operations
to change the name
from Sao Paulo
to Defiant.
The Breen are going
to be in for a surprise
when they train their
energy-dampening weapons
on this beauty, huh?
The shield generators
have been completely
reconfigured.
Let's go look.
You know what?
I, uh, want to check out
my Sick Bay.
Well, I'll let you two
get acquainted.
Hello, ship.
GARAK:
Cardassia.
It's as beautiful as I remember.
It won't be beautiful to my eyes
until the Dominion is gone.
Orbital Traffic Control
is asking for our
security clearance.
GARAK:
I'll handle it.
We're taking a big risk
coming here.
I hope it's worth it.
Gul Revok
and Legate Goris
are ready to bring their
troops over to our side.
That's over
a half a million men.
If we can convince Gul Seltan
to join us as well
that's another 100,000.
I think that is
worth the risk.
And you're sure
you want me around?
Before they join us,
they'll want assurances
that the Federation
will support them.
We've been cleared
for standard orbit.
Do you have transport
coordinates?
Yes. Transporter room
is standing by.
Then the Bridge
is yours, Seskal.
Good luck.
( shouting and weapons' fire)
( screaming )
Is that all
of them?
Yes, sir.
Check the other
side of the cave!
Inform the First
that we have killed
all the traitors.
How did they know?
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
I told you I could
lure them here for you.
Gul Revok.
He betrayed us.
Kira to Seskal.
Get us out of here.
We're under attack!
I can't lower the shields!
Lock the disruptors
and return fire!
Transfer the auxiliary
power to...
( screaming )
Seskal?
Seskal, do you read me?
I don't think
they're up there anymore.
We've got to get out of here.
No.
Damar, do you know
any place we can go?
Everyone I know
on Cardassia
has either been
arrested or killed.
I think I know someone
who might take us in.
That is, if we can
get to the capital.
Well, we can't stay here.
MILA:
If you don't mind hiding
in a basement
then I guess I don't mind
having you down here.
I don't hear from
you for years
and then you show up
on my doorstep
with these people.
GARAK:
I do apologize for the intrusion
but you're the only person
on Cardassia I could trust.
MILA:
Well, don't blame me if you
don't have any friends left.
Well, now, where's
that light switch?
GARAK:
It's smaller than I remember.
I grew up in
this house.
Did I mention that?
I thought you said
Enabran Tain used
to live here.
Tain was Garak's father.
He was unable to
acknowledge it publicly
because he was head
of the Obsidian Order.
Mila was our housekeeper
and most trusted confidante.
I was never much of a cook
but I knew how to keep a secret.
We have to contact the
other resistance cells
and warn them
about Revok.
Is there any way you
can get us a com unit?
If it's not too much
of an imposition.
You shouldn't be involved
in this.
We're attempting
to free our people.
Do you want to live
under the Dominion
for the rest of your life?
( chuckles )
I'm an old woman.
I'm long past caring
about such things.
But I'll get you your com unit.
Mila...
thank you.
I promise we won't stay long.
Well, you might as well
make yourselves useful.
This place hasn't
been cleaned in years.
You heard the lady.
The glamour of being
a revolutionary, hmm?
Well, everything
checks out fine.
I'm certifying you
fit for duty.
Finally. Last
time I spoke
with Kira, she wanted to know
when I'd be rejoining her.
Odo, um...
there is something
you need to know.
When I first discovered
that you had become infected
with the morphogenic virus
I assumed you'd contracted it
from the Founders.
Didn't I?
No.
The fact is, it was you
who transmitted
the disease to them.
But...
how did I get it?
You were deliberately infected.
By whom?
Section 31.
They used you
as a carrier
hoping you would pass on
the disease to the Founders.
I'm sure you
were never meant
to develop
symptoms, but...
I don't care whether
they meant to kill me or not.
The reality is, the Federation
set out to destroy my people.
Section 31 aren't part
of the Federation.
They're a rogue organization...
Don't split hairs
with me, Doctor.
They used me
as an instrument
to try to commit genocide.
Now, we may be at war
with the Founders
but that's no excuse.
I completely agree.
And what does Starfleet
intend to do about it?
The Federation Council
considered giving
the Founders the cure.
Then they decided against it.
Then they're abetting genocide.
I don't condone
what Section 31 did
but the Founders
started this war, not us.
Giving them the cure
would strengthen their hand...
and we can't do that.
Not when there are still
millions of men and women
out there
putting their lives
on the line every day.
Well, I can see
there's no use protesting.
The decision's been made.
Odo, I wish I didn't
have to say this
but I need to know
you're not going to take
matters into your own hands.
You have my word.
That's all I needed to hear.
Interesting, isn't it?
The Federation claims
to abhor Section 31's
tactics, but when they need
their dirty work done
they look the other way.
It's a tidy little arrangement,
wouldn't you say?
Go ahead.
What have you got to lose?
Our jobs.
Let's do it.
At this point, I don't
care if he fires me.
That's the spirit.
Remember,
ask for ten percent
but settle for 15.
Okay.
Quark...
we have something
to say.
Then say it.
We don't think
we should have
to give you 20 percent
of our tips.
Mm-hmm.
We think ten percent
is more than fair
and we're not going back to
work until this is settled.
Ten percent?
Quark, there's an incoming
transmission from Ferenginar!
It's the Grand Nagus!
I'll take it in the back room.
LEETA:
Well?
I'll think about it.
What did he say?
He's going to
think about it.
( laughing )
( staticky ):
Is that you ...?
It's me.
I can barely see you.
It's the static.
Sorry about the static.
It's raining here.
It's always raining there.
Not this kind of rain.
...an accident
at the power plant.
The contractor used
substandard relays,
the greedy bastard.
There's a toxic electrostatic
cloud hanging over the city.
What a frigging mess.
So, what do I owe the pleasure?
The pressure?
That's an ungrateful thing
to say.
I'm not pressuring you.
No... "the pleasure."
You're not making any sense.
Now shut up and listen.
I'm retiring.
Your mother and I
are moving to Risa
to enjoy our old age
and do a lot of ...,
if you know what I mean.
Good for you...
I guess.
I'll be coming to Deep Space 9
to name my successor.
Why here?
Why do you think?
To get away from the rain?
No, my boy.
I've chosen you to succeed me.
You're going to be
the new Grand Nagus.
Congratulations....
( gasps )
( both gasping )
Oh, I'm sorry.
( laughing )
I'm sorry.
( both laughing )
I nearly... Hi.
Hi.
Your lunch?
Uh, it's that time.
Oh.
This is ridiculous.
I know.
I have a confession...
Listen, I've been
meaning to tell you...
You go first.
No, that's all right.
No, really, Julian.
You go first.
Okay.
You know how much
I value our friendship.
Well... lately,
I've been wondering
if... maybe we could be...
Something more?
Yes.
Exactly.
I've been wondering
the same thing.
Oh, I thought
it was just me.
Me, too.
That's why I've been
so awkward around you.
I've been trying to tell
you, but every time I...
It just...
I couldn't
get the words...
I know, what is that?
I don't...
( sighs )
I mean, I'm not
usually like this.
If, if I find
somebody attractive
I just, I just,
I just tell them
and I don't play
these ridiculous games.
Neither do I.
You know...
why we might
be holding back?
The friendship.
You're right.
Why jeopardize
our friendship
uh, by trying to turn this
into something else?
I've made
that mistake before.
Yes, and once you
cross the line...
You can never go back.
And if it
doesn't work out
you can never
be friends again.
I can't bear the thought
of losing you as a friend.
Neither can I.
So that's that.
We figured it out.
You know, it takes
a certain maturity
to not be swept away
by the romantic fantasy.
That's right.
Why let, uh...
physical attraction
overcome good sense?
Chemistry
isn't everything.
Absolutely not.
We're adults.
I think we should be
proud of ourselves.
So do I.
I feel much better.
Friends?
Friends.
Just think, this time next week
I'll be living
in the Nagal residence.
They say even
the waste extraction fixtures
are plated with latinum.
That's right!
( laughing )
Oh, oh, the first thing
I'm going to do
is rip them out and replace them
with solid latinum fixtures.
( laughing )
That's a little indulgent,
don't you think?
Of course.
That's the point.
A Nagus has to lead
by example.
My greed has to be
a shining light to everyone
a testament
to the rewards of avarice.
Now, I hope you're
not going to be lonely
in that great big
Nagal residence.
QUARK:
I've got a room
picked out for you
already, my dear
with a view
of the Tower of Commerce
and, uh, there'll be
a place for my dear brother
my brave nephew
and my lovely
sister-in-law.
Liquidator Brunt!
Uh, not him.
Uh-uh.
No. He's here.
What brings you here
this time, Brunt?
( scoffing laugh )
Ferenginar is rife
with rumors.
They say
the Grand Nagus is coming to DS9
to name his successor.
For once, the rumors...
are right.
I see.
A thousand...
congratulations, my Nagus.
He's not Nagus yet.
It's never too early
to suck up to the boss.
I think I'm going
to like being Nagus.
Don't stop.
...and thanks to the heroic
efforts of Gul Revok
Damar was lured to Cardassia
to meet with five other traitors
but his coconspirators
were killed
before they could begin plotting
against the people of Cardassia
and Damar himself was killed
while trying to penetrate
our defense perimeters
in a stolen Dominion vessel.
At least they're not looking
for us anymore.
WEYOUN:
...just hours ago
acting on information obtained
by our intelligence operatives
our brave troops began
a coordinated assault
on Damar's terrorist bases.
From Atbar Prime to Regulak IV,
from Simperia to Quinor VII
our forces eliminated
a total of 18 rebel bases.
With the rebellion crushed...
All 18?
...nothing can impede
our march to final victory.
Truly, this is a great day
for the Dominion.
How could they have compromised
our entire organization?
We took every
precaution
encrypted every
transmission, screened...
It doesn't matter
how they did it.
It's done.
Now we've got to find
a way off Cardassia.
Garak, can we use that thing
to contact
the Federation?
With a signal that strong,
the Dominion would trace
our location
in a matter of seconds.
Well, we've got to do something.
We are not spending
the rest of this war
in this cellar, are we?
Are we?
Financial advisor...
I don't know.
I do have lots of connections
on Ferenginar.
I don't need
your connections.
As Nagus, people
will be lining up
to do business with me.
You missed a spot.
Oh.
I'm sure there must
be something I can do
to make you
change your mind.
Possibly.
Would... 40 bricks
of gold-pressed latinum
do the trick?
No, but 70 would.
Fifty.
Sixty.
Done.
( laughing )
If you'll sign this.
What is it?
A receipt.
For a bribe?
Oh, surely you're aware
of the new regulation
making all bribes
tax-deductible.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Did you just use the T-word?
You mean "tax"?
Are you telling me there are...
Ts on Ferenginar?
You haven't been keeping up
with the latest reforms,
have you?
Zek instituted
progressive income tax
three months ago.
You call that a reform?
Taxes go against the very spirit
of free enterprise.
That's why they
call it "free."
The government needed revenues
to fund
the new social programs--
wage subsidies
for the poor
retirement benefits
for the aged
health care for...
Stop, stop, stop.
I had no idea
things had gotten so bad.
This is all Moogie's fault.
She's been polluting Zek's mind
with notions of equality
and compassion.
Whatever happened
to survival of the fittest?
to the rich getting richer
and the poor getting poorer?
Whatever happened
to pure, unadulterated...
Greed.
greed?
Well, things change.
And they're going
to change back.
The first thing I'm going to do
is eliminate
these so-called reforms
before Ferenginar ends
up looking like a...
Federation planet.
Oh, I'm not sure
the Congress of Economic
Advisors will approve.
I don't care who they are
or what they are.
As Nagus, I can do what I want.
Not anymore.
All regulations
proposed by the Nagus
have to be ratified
by the Congress
before they become law.
Oh, you'll still be
a powerful man.
I wouldn't be sucking up
to you otherwise.
Blessed Exchequer, forgive us.
Your children
have gone astray.
( door opens )
MILA:
If only they could see you now.
Who?
The people in
the streets.
Everyone's talking
about Damar
and his rebels.
What are they saying?
How stupid we were for walking
into a Dominion trap?
How arrogant we were
to think we could beat them
in the first place?
How glad they are
that we're all dead?
Actually, they don't
really believe you are dead.
Oh, you should
hear the stories.
"Damar is alive.
"My cousin saw him
on Kelvas Prime."
"He faked his own death."
"He is plotting
"a new offensive
from his secret
mountain hideaway."
You never told me you had
a secret mountain hideaway.
I was going to surprise you.
I wonder why they refuse
to believe you're dead.
Oh, they've been lied to
so often.
They don't trust anything
the Dominion says.
No, what if it's more than that?
What if we had
more of an impact
than we realized?
What if we turned you
into a legend?
( snorts )
Some legend.
Don't you see?
The people want
to believe in you.
We can use that.
Yes, the organized resistance
is gone
but there's an entire
civilian population out there
that is fed up with living
under the occupation
and if Damar,
the man they couldn't kill
tells the people of Cardassia
to rise up
against the Dominion...
Then we might have
a revolution on our hands.
Or you might really
get yourselves killed.
Anything's better
than rotting in this cellar.
How do we begin?
Where's the closest
Jem'Hadar barracks?
( door chimes )
Come in.
( electronically
distorted voice )
Allow me to present Gul--
no, I'm sorry-- Legate Broca
the new leader
of the Cardassian Union.
I serve the Founders
in all things.
Your service is noted.
Thot Pran, I look forward
to working with you
and the Breen
Confederacy.
( distorted voice )
Your first task
will be to make
a formal address to
the Cardassian people
assuring them that
the Dominion has
their best
interests...
That can wait.
But it can wait.
Now that the rebellion
has been crushed
it is time to turn our attention
to strategic
matters.
The enemy has devised
a countermeasure
to our energy-dampening weapons.
Therefore,
we must alter our tactics.
We are falling back.
( distorted voice )
No.
I don't mean surrender.
Perish the thought.
The Dominion has never
surrendered in battle
since its founding
10,000 years ago.
I am ordering our troops
to retreat to Cardassian space.
We will establish
a new line of defense
along this perimeter.
With less territory to defend,
we can concentrate our troops
and hold off any attack
if the enemy attacks at all.
The Federation is,
by its very nature, timid.
When they see we've pulled back,
their first impulse will be
to leave us alone.
Well, what about the Klingons
and the Romulans
and the...?
I meant no disrespect.
I was simply asking a question.
Without the Federation,
the others are no threat to us.
Once the new perimeter
is established
we will redouble
our shipbuilding efforts
and increase production
of Jem'Hadar troops.
Retreat may prolong the war,
but in the end
we will emerge stronger
and in a far better position
to take the Alpha Quadrant
once and for all.
QUARK:
Did you know this Congress
of Economic Meddlers
actually passed legislation
making monopolies illegal?
What's the point
of being in business
if you can't
corner the market--
gouge your customers?
There's something to be said
for keeping prices down
by ensuring
healthy competition.
So... what are you
going to do with the bar?
You can't even dump
industrial waste anymore
because it might harm
"the natural habitat."
I'm supposed to start
worrying about animals now.
Look how they live--
wallowing in dirt,
sleeping in trees.
That's not natural.
I suppose you could argue
that Ferenginar's biodiversity
is a precious resource
that belongs to everyone.
So... what are you going
to do with the bar?
And don't even get me started
about this whole
"labor rights" thing.
What have we come to
if you can't demand
sexual favors
from the people in your employ?
Unharassed workers
are productive workers.
So... what are you going to do
with the bar?!
Sell it!
What would I want with it
anymore?
I'll give you
5,000 bars of latinum
and not one slip more.
That's reasonable.
It is?
I'm telling you, Rom,
our people have lost their way.
I just happen to have a contract
right here.
I read a report that over
40 percent of the population
no longer believes
that you have to buy your way
into the Divine Treasury
when you die.
Can I have your thumbprint
here, please?
They don't teach children
the Rules of
Acquisition anymore!
And another print here.
There's a disease...
spreading
through Ferengi society.
It's making us soft.
( thumbprint registers )
The 5,000 has been transferred
to your account.
It was a pleasure
doing business with you.
5,000?
I thought you were going to hold
me up for at least eight.
I didn't even haggle with you.
I know!
It really threw me off.
What's wrong with me?
Don't worry, Brother.
You're going to be so rich
what's a few thousand
bars of latinum?
I've been infected, too.
I haven't raised prices
in months.
I've even been considering
letting the dabo girls
keep most of their tips.
I've gone soft!
I kind of like you better
this way.
I don't...
and I'm going to do
something about it.
This disease
has got to be stopped
before it destroys everything
Ferenginar stands for.
If Zek wants me to be Nagus
he's going to have
to let me do things
my way, or else...
I'll turn down the job!
Are you serious?!
You bet I am.
But being Nagus
will make you rich.
I don't care.
I won't preside over the demise
of Ferengi civilization.
Not me!
The line has to be drawn here!
This far and no further!
This way.
He's been in there too long.
Something's wrong.
You there. Stop.
Let me see
your work order.
But I showed it to you
on the way in.
This has not been
approved by the First.
( laughing ):
Ah! Yes.
I can explain that.
How much time?
The detonator only had
a three-minute delay.
The bomb could go off
any second now.
GARAK ( faintly ):
Gentlemen, this is ridiculous.
Come on, Garak.
We have to do something.
I don't know why you're making
such a fuss over this.
I have a busy repair schedule
and I can't stand here
all night...
You will wait here
till the First arrives.
GARAK:
And how long
will that be?
You will wait!
DAMAR:
You! Jem'Hadar!
Who are you to treat
a Cardassian citizen like that?
It's him-- Damar!
Hold him here.
Surrender yourself, or die.
I choose neither.
( yelling )
Back, get back!
( explosions and screaming )
( coughing )
It's Damar.
It's Damar!
He's alive!
Citizens of Cardassia, hear me.
The Dominion told you that
the rebellion has been crushed.
What you have seen here today
proves that that is
yet another lie.
Our fight for freedom continues
but it will take place here
in the streets.
I call on Cardassians everywhere
to rise up.
Rise up and join me.
I need you to be my army.
If we stand together,
nothing can oppose us.
Freedom is ours for the taking!
Freedom!
( all yelling ):
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
Freedom! Freedom!
( yelling continues )
( chanting ):
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
Good morning.
( chuckling )
What?
What are you smiling at?
You know,
I was thinking.
If it hadn't been
for our little talk
the other day
we'd probably be
just standing here
staring at our shoes.
No, not a chance.
I'd have turned
and walked the other way
as soon as I saw you.
I'm glad we've got
it all behind us.
Me, too.
Excuse me.
Huh. I guess they
worked it out.
It always brings
a tear to my eye
to see a Nagus
pass his staff
to a successor.
( chuckling )
It's a privilege to witness
such a historic moment.
Just wait and see.
It's going to be more
historic than you think.
They're here!
There you are, my boy.
I have...
something for you.
Not so fast, Zek.
We need to talk.
I knew you were going
to make this difficult.
My mind is made up, Quark.
Whining and complaining
won't do anything.
I won't have anything to do
with what you're doing
to our once proud civilization.
A man can only
be pushed so far.
If you want me to be Nagus
you're going to have
to let me do things my way.
Who wants you
to be Nagus?
Out of the way, Quark.
Congratulations, Rom.
You're going to make
a fine Nagus.
I am?
What's wrong?
You seemed so happy
when I talked to you
the other day.
I did?
That was me.
You?!
Oh. I thought
I was talking to Rom.
Must have been all the static.
Glad we cleared
that up.
This is insane.
You actually want
Rom to be Nagus?
It was my idea.
Figures.
He's an idiot.
You've always
underestimated
your brother.
Shh!
A new Ferenginar
needs a new kind of Nagus--
a kinder, gentler Nagus--
( disgusted sigh )
and that's you, my boy.
It's a great
responsibility
to stand at the bow
of the Ferengi ship of state.
A Nagus has to navigate
the waters of
the Great Material
Continuum,
avoid the Shoals
of Bankruptcy
and seek the
Strong Winds
of Prosperity.
I'll do the best I can.
May I be the first
to offer my congratulations?
LEETA:
Oh, Rom!
Way to go, Dad.
( laughing )
All right, you want Rom?
You can have him.
In fact, you deserve him.
He's perfect for this new
workers' paradise of yours.
He can save the environment
and levy all the taxes he wants.
He's not taking
it very well.
In fact, as far
as I'm concerned...
the Ferenginar that I knew
doesn't exist anymore.
No... I take that back.
It will exist,
right here in this bar.
This establishment
will be the last outpost
of what made Ferenginar great--
the unrelenting lust
for profit!
Broik, water the drinks!
M'Pella, rig the dabo table!
Rom... I want
to buy back the bar.
That's all right, Brother.
I'll give it to you.
I suppose you're going to let me
keep the 5,000 bars
of latinum, too.
You're my brother.
And you're an idiot.
But I love you.
Congratulations.
You're the perfect Nagus
for this new Ferenginar.
Are you sure we picked
the right brother?
Come, my dear.
Risa's waiting.
( Zek laughing )
Good luck, kid!
You're going
to need it.
I'm proud of you, son.
Let's go, Zekkie.
You know... I could use
a financial advisor.
No kidding, but it's
not going to be me.
I know someone
who's available.
Forget it!
Not so hasty-- let him
give you a pedicure first.
Now, if you'll
excuse me
I've got to get
back to work.
There's money
to be made.
How can I serve you, my...
Wow.
According to our
intelligence reports
the Dominion has
withdrawn completely
from Klingon, Federation,
and Romulan space.
They seem to be forming
a new defensive perimeter
within Cardassian territory.
They must know
we've developed
a countermeasure
to the Breen weapon.
That would be my guess.
There are advantages
to falling back.
They shorten
their supply lines
while forcing us
to lengthen ours.
ROSS:
And with a smaller
perimeter
they're less vulnerable
to hit-and-run attacks.
It would take
a major offensive
to break through
their lines.
At a cost of
thousands of ships.
The wiser course
would be to simply
contain them within
their perimeter.
That's what
they're hoping we'll do--
to give them time
to rebuild their forces.
He's right.
We have them
on the defensive.
We should hit them
with everything we've got.
Breaking through that line
would be a very ugly,
very bloody job.
If we do nothing
the Dominion could sit
behind that perimeter
for the next five years
rearming themselves
and when they're ready
to come out, God help us all.
The Klingon Empire
votes to attack now
before they have
time to recover.
Considering the
alternatives...
I'm afraid
I have to concur.
Very well.
Then it's settled.
We attack.
You're up late.
You waiting for me?
What's wrong?
I'm pregnant.
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure.
Oh.
Baby, I...
I didn't mean...
A... a baby.
You and me....
a... wow.
Surprise.
"Surprise" is right.
Uh... how did... you...?
One of us...
forgot our injection
last month.
( sighs )
Julian reminded me of that.
It's just that the way things
have been going on...
You don't have to apologize.
I'm not!
Are you kidding?
This... this is wonderful.
I'm glad you think so.
But you don't.
I just keep thinking
about the Prophets.
They warned you
that marrying me
would bring you sorrow.
Kasidy, we have
been through this.
I know we have, and I...
I know that we said
we wouldn't let the Prophets
run our lives
but that was...
( sighs )
that was before this.
What if...
what if they were trying
to tell you something?
That something would
happen to our baby?
Shh.
Nothing... is going
to happen to our baby.
Are you sure?
( whispering ):
I am the Emissary
of the Prophets
and I know that nothing
is going to happen.
Everything is going
to be all right.
( whispering ):
I hope you're right.
We're going to have a baby.
A baby.