( computer beeps )
COMPUTER: The time is 0500.
Mmm... yeah, all right...
Julian?
Yes.
We have to get up.
Yeah, sure.
It's a big day.
( satisfied sigh )
It was a big night.
( laughs softly )
Cleared up a lot of unanswered questions.
Such as?
Such as just how far
these spots really go down.
I suppose you'll want to tell Miles.
Now why would I want to do that?
Because you tell him everything.
True.
But you know what?
In this case...
I'm going to make an exception.
Good.
( sighs )
Mmm... we really should get up.
We don't want the Defiant
leaving without us.
You know, I've never been into battle
with someone I've slept with before.
Well, there's a first time for everything.
Now that we're finally together
it'd be such a shame
if something happened to one of us.
Let's make a pact.
We both come home alive.
You got yourself a deal.
I'm holding you to that.
Oh, and don't forget,
Kirayoshi has his checkup
at 0900 tomorrow.
I've already confirmed
the appointment with Nurse Bandee.
Come on, sweetie, one more bite.
And don't stay up all night
writing that paper on...
W--what are those trees called?
Arfillian Ficus.
And they're not trees, they're shrubs.
Yeah, well... try to get some sleep.
Oh, and--
Honey... we'll be fine. Stop worrying.
Right.
Molly...
please don't touch that.
I let you play with my toys.
Yeah, but, see, this isn't a toy.
This is a... model.
Maybe it belongs in a museum then.
I suppose I could give it to Julian.
Sounds good to me.
Speaking of Julian have you told him
about Starfleet's offer yet?
Uh... no, not yet.
I knew it.
What's that supposed to mean?
We're not going back to Earth.
Of course we are.
Daddy's going to teach at the Academy...
when the war's over.
Then why haven't you told Julian?
"Out of the mouth of babes."
I'll tell him, you know... when...
I think he's ready to hear it.
How's that?
Oh, it's doing wonders for my head
but it's my stomach that's bothering me.
If it will help, morning sickness ends
after the first trimester.
Oh, that's two more months.
I don't think I'm going to make it.
You're going to make it.
-Ben?
-Hmm?
Promise me something.
Promise that you'll come home to us.
I promise.
I don't believe it.
I said I promise.
No, it's not...
( groaning )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hey, I thought I'd walk you
to the Defiant.
I'd like that.
Ah.
How's Kas?
( coughing and retching )
Reports of my death
have been exaggerated...
but not by much.
( groaning )
Isn't there something
she can take to make her feel better?
She doesn't like taking medication
unless it's absolutely necessary.
( groaning )
Sounds necessary to me.
Waiting for you to leave
only makes me feel worse.
If you're going to go, just go.
Are you sure I can't get you anything?
Just hurry up and come back home.
( groaning )
Mind if I walk with you, Commander?
Not at all.
Captain Sisko informed me that you would
be joining us on the mission.
I hope that when we reach Cardassia
we find Colonel Kira alive and well.
So do I, Commander. So do I.
NOG: Captain on the Bridge.
All right, people.
What do you say we end this war?
Sounds good to me.
Ensign, I believe you know
the way to Cardassia.
If I get lost, I'll just
follow the ship in front of us.
WEYOUN: The Federation invasion fleet
has left Deep Space 9.
They'll reach the Cardassian
border by tomorrow night.
( electronically distorted voice )
Our brave Jem'Hadar soldiers
have a motto,"Victory is life."
( distorted voice )
I'm glad you're familiar with it,
because today those words
have meaning for us all.
The outcome of this battle will determine
the outcome of the war.
Either we destroy their invasion forces
or they destroy us.
There is no other option.
( distorted voice )
Fight well today...
and Romulus will be yours
to do with as you wish.
( distorted voice )
Yes, yes. And Earth, too.
I assure you... the pleasure is all mine.
( distorted voice )
Is something bothering you?
Apparently, uh...
I was under the mistaken impression
that all Federation territories
would fall under my jurisdiction...
including Earth.
And so they shall.
But...
you promised the Breen.
I would promise the Breen
the entire Alpha Quadrant
if I thought it would help win this war.
The Founder is wise in all things.
( door opening )
Founder, I've heard a disturbing rumor
about the traitor Damar.
What about him?
He may be alive.
Is this possible?
I don't see how.
We destroyed his ship, his rebel bases...
But his body was never found.
They say he's here... on Cardassia Prime.
In the capital, no less.
Look into this matter.
-If Damar is alive...
-He won't be for long.
JEM HADAR SOLDIER: Halt!
Step forward... slowly.
I'm sorry, have we done something wrong?
We're new to the city
and I'm afraid we're lost.
Quiet!
You are Legate Damar.
I told you-- you look just like him.
I can't tell you how many times
my cousin
has been mistaken for that traitor.
He will be taken to Dominion headquarters.
You will die here.
( distorted voice )
I do not understand you.
( groaning )
I don't mean to sound ungrateful, but...
what are you doing here?
Watching your backs.
I thought we decided it would be safer
if you stayed out of sight.
Well, that's what the helmet's for.
You should be wearing one, too.
Every Jem'Hadar and Breen soldier
on Cardassia's looking for you.
If I'm to lead this revolt
I can't do it hiding in a cellar.
It was necessary for me
to attend that gathering tonight.
Well, fill me in later.
If anyone stops us, you're my prisoners.
But the vote was unanimous.
The work disruptions begin tomorrow.
Power, communication
and transportation facilities
throughout Cardassia will be sabotaged.
The Dominion fleet will be cut off
from all ground support.
That way, they'll have to face
the invasion force on their own.
And once the Dominion is crushed...
MILA: All Cardassia will be free again.
Oh, when you were a small boy
I was worried about you.
Always getting into trouble.
So secretive, so full of deceit.
Who would've thought
those disgraceful characteristics
would be turned to virtues.
-More tea?
-You're too kind.
Do you hear that, Chief?
Sounds like the Doppler
compensators are out of phase.
Ensign, how's she handling?
She's not quite as smooth
as the old Defiant, sir.
Feels a bit sluggish.
Chief?
I'm on it. O'Brien to Engineering.
CREWMAN: ( on com ) Engineering.
Recalibrate the inertial dampers
and check the plasma flow regulators
while you're at it.
CREWMAN: Right away, Chief.
You think someone would've come up
with a better inertial control system.
What's that, Miles?
I said, I wish you'd wipe
that grin off your face.
You're not the first person
to fall in love, you know.
-I thought you'd be happy for me.
-I am happy for you.
O'Brien to Engineering.
CREWMAN: Engineering.
Now try realigning the induction coils.
Will do.
You're sure you're not angry.
Why should I be angry?
I have been asking you to tell the doctor
how you feel about him for the past month.
Well... now that he knows how I feel...
I am happy for you.
That's a relief.
But... I am going to kill him.
You're kidding, right?
And Jadzia said I did not
have a sense of humor.
Julian, there's something
I need to talk to you about.
You're getting pressure
from Keiko, aren't you?
How did you know?
It's a big decision.
I'm surprised it didn't come up sooner.
Actually we've been talking
about it for quite a while.
Well, you can stop talking about it.
We'll move the Alamo into my quarters.
NOG: I could still use a little more
equalization on the torque buffers.
Uh, right.
I'll try to compensate
with the impulse response filters.
That way, your quarters
won't be so cluttered
and, uh, you can still use it
whenever you want.
I wasn't talking about the Alamo model.
Besides, it's too big for your quarters.
You let me worry about that.
So... what were you talking about?
Oh, it's nothing that can't wait.
Is that any better, Nog?
Torque buffers are stable.
I wish she were here, too, Constable.
If we only knew where Kira was.
If we could only be sure
that she was all right.
The Colonel's a survivor.
This war, Captain... it has to end.
And it will... soon.
One way or the other.
Mother?
The Emissary's task is nearing completion.
Are you talking about the war?
You have walked the path
the Prophets laid out for you, Benjamin.
Do not falter now.
I don't intend to.
Know this... my son.
Your journey's end lies not before you...
but behind you.
ODO: Captain?
Captain...
The Prophets...
came to me in a vision.
I take it they weren't bringing good news.
I'm not sure.
Only time will tell.
( door opening )
Hello, Adami.
You're back.
( sighs )
Is that all you have to say to me?
I see the Pah-wraiths
have restored your sight.
Yes, they've forgiven me.
I was hoping you could find it
in your heart to do the same.
I don't forgive war criminals.
To think I took Gul Dukat to my bed
one of the most hated men
in Bajoran history.
I've already told you
how much I regret my actions
during the occupation.
Of course you do.
Have you learned how to release
the Pah-wraiths?
The secrets of the Kosst Amojan
have been revealed to me, yes.
Then why haven't you gone
to the Fire Caves and freed them?
I was waiting for you.
Then you do forgive me.
I need your help, Dukat.
It's as simple as that.
All you have to do is ask.
Together, we will release the Pah-wraiths
so they can lay claim
to the Celestial Temple
and destroy the Prophets.
And their Emissary.
No, no, no.
Benjamin Sisko will be dealt with by me...
and me alone.
Assuming he survives
the invasion of Cardassia.
Oh, he'll survive...
but I promise you...
he'll wish he hadn't.
You going to sit there all night, Quark?
Got any... threes?
Go fish.
Don't tell me you're quitting?
It's just not my game.
Well, you want to try pinochle again?
How about rummy? Or gin rummy?
Five card stud?
Uh, canasta?
How about some tongo?
Did they play tongo in Las Vegas in 1962?
How could they? It's a Ferengi game.
Which is why my holographic
program can't create it.
I know, I know.
This place is period specific.
For a hologram,
you're not very accommodating.
Oh, is that why you dropped by,
to insult me?
I dropped by
because I had nothing else to do.
My bar hasn't had half a dozen
customers all day.
Everyone's off fighting this stupid war.
It's not easy staying behind, is it?
Knowing your friends are out there
risking their lives?
They think they have it rough?
They should try leading my life for a day.
The hospitality industry
isn't for the fainthearted.
A bartender's life is a lonely one.
That's true, but few people understand it.
They think it's one big happy party.
They forget that the person
giving the party never has any fun.
He's too busy making sure
everyone else is having fun.
All I do, all day long,
is give, give, give.
Bartending is a very noble profession
and you do it well
under some very difficult circumstances
I might add.
You should be proud.
Think so?
I know so, pally.
I just hope Nog...
and the rest of those heroic idiots
come back in one piece.
There you are.
Vic, sweetie, are you ready?
Jimmy and Peter are about to go on.
Sorry, pally, got to run.
Durante and Lawford are at the Sands.
Can't miss that.
I thought you said a bartender's life
was a lonely one.
It is, but I'm not a bartender.
Huh.
Go fish.
( groaning )
Is it really necessary to rest so often?
You don't need to wait for me.
Go on ahead.
Wander aimlessly through these caves
for the rest of your miserable life.
I'm in no hurry.
During the occupation
my people found the Bajorans' fear
of these caves amusing...
and yet, we never took
the time to visit them...
and now here I am.
It's ironic, isn't it?
I don't care.
Excuse me, I just meant--
I'm sure you
have many interesting anecdotes
about the occupation
but I don't have any desire to hear them.
I meant no disrespect, Adami.
And stop calling me "Adami."
That privilege is no longer yours.
How should I address you, then?
From now on, you will address me
as "Eminence."
Is that clear?
Perfectly...
Eminence.
I see your point
but for two millennia,
the Jem'Hadar have been
the Dominion's first line of defense.
It would damage their morale
to have to take a backseat to the Breen.
( distorted voice )
Very well.
In the spirit of our new alliance
I will inform the Jem'Hadar
that the Breen forces will stand
alongside them.
( distorted voice )
I'm glad that pleases you.
I think we have a problem.
( distorted voice )
Our lines are spread too thin,
especially here, at the center.
WEYOUN: We need to dispatch
reinforcements immediately.
-Do you agree?
-( distorted voice )
Notify the Jem'Hadar.
Order them to reinforce
the center of their lines.
Now what?
( distorted voice )
COMPUTER: Emergency power engaged.
Founder, I'm relieved
to see that you're all right.
WEYOUN: Long-range
communications are down.
I can't contact the Jem'Hadar.
-( distorted voice )
-Of course I'll keep trying.
-What caused the power failure?
-I'm afraid it was sabotage.
Almost every Dominion installation
on Cardassian Prime has suffered damage.
Damar.
We captured some of the terrorists
but they're not soldiers,
they're ordinary citizens.
Are you telling me
that the Cardassian people
are rising up against us?
I'm sure it's only a small
number of malcontents.
But we have no way of knowing that, do we?
Founder, may I make a suggestion?
Yes, I am sure that Broca
will be very happy
to hear what you have to say.
If the Cardassian people are responsible
for these acts of terrorism...
if Damar and his fanatics
have turned them against us
then it's the people
who should be punished.
Now, what do you say to that?
( strained ) Severely punished.
Well, I'm glad we all agree.
See to it.
DAMAR: It's been 24 minutes.
Not bad.
If the Dominion hasn't been able
to restore power to the capital
then the entire planet must be in chaos.
I hope so.
I'm afraid I was only able
to find two more light sticks.
There's more about the house
somewhere, but I--
Would you stop dawdling
and give them to me?
Oh, well, I remember that tone of voice.
It reminds me of the demanding
and inconsiderate boy you used to be.
I haven't changed much, have I?
DAMAR: This will send a clear message
to the Dominion,
the Cardassian people will fight
to regain their freedom.
I hope they realize
their fight is just beginning.
We're going to have to hit the enemy again
and harder this time.
Well, that won't be easy.
They will have tightened their security.
Well, that doesn't matter.
We can't lose our momentum.
The Commander is right.
We cannot rest until Cardassia is free.
And when it is,
we'll have you to thank for it.
Without you, this rebellion
would have died in its infancy.
Ironic, isn't it? The savior of Cardassia
a former Bajoran terrorist?
Well, don't canonize me just yet.
It's been 26 and a half minutes.
Let's see what the Dominion
has to say for itself.
Citizens of Cardassia
this latest wave of vandalism
directed against
your Dominion allies must stop.
I wouldn't count on it.
WEYOUN: We know that these disgraceful
acts of sabotage
were carried out
by a mere handful of extremists
but these radicals must come to realize
that their disobedience
will not be tolerated.
That you, the Cardassian people,
will suffer the consequences
of their cowardly actions.
Which is why I must inform you,
a few moments ago
Dominion troops
reduced Lakarian City to ashes.
There were no survivors.
Two million men, women and children
gone in a matter of moments.
For each act of sabotage
committed against the Dominion
another Cardassian city will be destroyed.
I implore you not to let that happen.
Let us return to the spirit
of friendship and cooperation
between our peoples
so that together, we can destroy
our common enemies
the Federation, the Klingons, the Romulans
and all the others that stand against us.
Thank you.
I should have killed
that Vorta jackal when I had the chance.
You want another one?
We'll attack Dominion Headquarters.
Chop off a snake's head
and the body will die.
KIRA: Exactly.
Damar, for the past two years
you've practically lived in that building.
If you're asking me
if I know a way in the answer is no,
not without a valid security protocol.
All right, we'll use force.
We're going to need
some kind of explosives.
I'll get right on it.
What you're proposing is suicide.
If you have nothing positive
to say, Mila...
All right, I'll prepare some food.
Nobody should die on an empty stomach.
Sir, Chancellor Martok
would like to speak to you
and Admiral Ross.
Put them through.
MARTOK: Gentlemen...
a magnificent victory lies before us.
I trust those
are prophetic words, Chancellor.
They are... and I've not forgotten
the promise I made to both of you.
That the three of us would share
a bottle of bloodwine on Cardassia Prime.
"A bottle"?
( chuckles )
I brought a barrel of 2309.
There is no finer vintage.
Then I'll meet you both on Cardassia.
We'll see who gets there first.
The Chancellor makes victory sound easy.
He knows it won't be. Sisko to all hands.
Prepare to engage the enemy.
I'll say one thing for the Breen,
they know how to pilot their ships.
-So do you, Ensign.
-Stay with him.
I'm trying, but he's slippery.
Mr. Worf?
Unable to lock target.
We have two Jem'Hadar ships
closing aft of us, bearing 136 mark 4.
Evasive action, pattern delta.
Hang on.
Well done, Ensign.
But I lost the Breen ship we were after.
I wouldn't worry about it.
There are plenty more to choose from.
You've hardly touched your meal.
No wonder you're not looking well.
I'm not looking well
because I live in a cellar.
Well, so does Legate Damar.
And what about him?
Well, he's finished
everything on his plate
which explains
why he is such a fine,
handsome figure of a man.
Oh, I'm afraid I don't follow you.
I do. Mila, I believe
you're falling in love.
Oh, I'm old enough to be his mother.
Ah-ah.
Nonsense.
Politicians.
( door chimes )
Now, who could that be?
Uh... I'll go see.
Uh, may I help you?
( whispering ) What's taking her so long?
I don't know.
( door opening )
( loud thud )
Mila!
KIRA: Garak!
Garak, get out of there!
( grunting )
( coughing )
( grunting in pain )
( grunts )
I can't look away for a second.
Just fix the shoulder.
Careful!
Sit still or you'll end up
with one arm shorter than the other.
You'd do anything to beat me at darts.
I haven't lost a game to you in months.
I'm going to miss our games, Julian.
What are you talking about?
You're going to be fine.
I'm leaving DS9, Julian.
I'm moving back to Earth.
Why?
I've been offered
a position at the Starfleet Academy...
Professor of Engineering.
When?
When the war's over.
Oh... I see.
Somebody has to teach you officers
the difference between a warp matrix
flux capacitor
and a self-sealing stem bolt.
Of course, of course.
( computer beeping )
EZRI: Captain, Admiral Ross for you.
On screen.
ROSS: The Romulan flagship's
been destroyed.
Their entire line is collapsing.
We'll try to help.
With what?
Ben, we're losing too many ships.
We've got to find a way to turn
the Dominion's left flank.
It's too well protected
but their lines are spread
pretty thin in the middle.
You help the Romulans.
Martok and I will hit the center.
On my way.
Dax, have attack wings
64 and 65 follow us.
Aye, sir.
What's taking so long?
Our engineers have assured me
that our long-range communications
will be restored momentarily.
But you have been saying that for hours
and meantime, there's no way
of contacting our ships
no way of knowing
how the battle is progressing.
BROCA: Founder
our troops have captured
the traitor Damar.
Finally... some good news.
And there's more. Colonel Kira
and Garak have been apprehended with him.
Even better.
Shall I have them brought here?
What for?
Have them executed...
immediately.
With pleasure
Understood. It will be done at once.
On your feet.
Why?
We prefer our prisoners
to be standing when they die.
Does anyone have any last words?
You may kill us,
but Cardassia will never--
JEM'HADAR: Enough.
-Final words are not permitted.
-How disappointing.
Ready weapons.
On my mark.
That's for Lakarian City.
Legate Damar, I pledge my life
to free Cardassia from the Dominion.
With men like you on our side...
how can we fail?
( yells )
Jem'Hadar ship off the port bow.
WORF: Shields are down to 60 percent.
Miles, this is no good.
I'm going to have to get you to Sick Bay.
-I'm kind of busy right now.
-That's an order.
-Look, Julian!
-You heard him, Chief.
Yes, sir.
Another Jem'Hadar to port.
( console beeping )
Transferring auxiliary power
to the port shields.
Dax, we need some support
from our attack fighters.
Aye, sir.
Breen ship off the starboard aft.
EZRI: Sir, most of our fighters
are either destroyed
or under attack themselves.
Ensign, get us out of here.
I'm trying, sir.
Sir, the Cardassians... they're attacking
the other Dominion ships.
They've switched sides.
Yes!
The timing couldn't be better.
Come about and head
for the center of their lines.
This is our chance to punch through.
NOG: Aye, sir.
Founder, our long-range communications
are back on line.
It's about time.
I don't believe it.
What now?
The Cardassian fleet
has turned against us.
( distorted voice )
Have our forces pull back
and regroup at Cardassia Prime.
But we'll be totally surrounded.
There will be no more running.
( distorted voice )
We should've rid ourselves
of the Cardassians
at the first sign of rebellion.
If I could talk to the rebels
get them to change their minds.
Perhaps you could reawaken
their patriotic spirit.
Exactly.
On the other hand, they're just as likely
to convince you to betray us.
Me? Betray you?
-Never!
-That's right.
We are not going to give you
that opportunity.
Wait! You're making a terrible mistake.
I don't think so.
But I've done everything you've asked.
I tell you, I'm loyal!
I believe in the Dominion! No! Wait! No!
I won't miss him.
I want the Cardassians exterminated.
Which ones?
-All of them, the entire population.
-That will take some time.
Then I suggest that you begin at once.
Captain, the Dominion forces
are retreating towards Cardassia Prime.
Sir? Admiral Ross and Chancellor Martok
would like to talk to you.
On screen.
I never thought I'd say this
but thank God for the Cardassians.
As I predicted, the day is ours.
Not yet, it isn't.
Ben, we've driven the Dominion
back into Cardassia Prime.
We can keep them bottled up
there indefinitely.
What if they use this time
to rebuild their fleet?
He's right. The Dominion
has displayed an ability
to build ships at an impressive rate.
We should continue the attack.
At what cost?
We've already lost a third of our fleet.
Then we must see to it
that those soldiers did not die in vain.
Admiral, with the Cardassians joining us
we have an opportunity
to put an end to this war
once and for all.
All right, gentlemen. We press on.
My friends,
songs will be sung about this day.
All right, people... you heard the orders.
Let's finish what we started.
DUKAT: Let me guess...
we're here.
We've reached the end of one journey
and stand ready to begin another.
What's the matter, Dukat?
You look disappointed.
Well, this may sound naive,
but I was expecting to see fire.
They are called the fire caves.
And with good reason.
Lano ka'la bo'shar lanu no'vala
pahrom carana mokado ba'jah.
Ko'se nusso ma'kora kajani...
lano ka'la Kosst Amojan.
Is that better?
According to this map, it's a long way
from the cargo door to the briefing room.
Well, that could be a problem
if we get trapped in the corridor.
-( explosion )
-What the hell?
It's the Jem'Hadar. They're leveling
the city, building by building.
All right, we have to go now.
Once we get inside the complex
we stop at nothing
until we capture the changeling.
SOLDIER: Let it be done! We're with you!
For Cardassia!
ALL: For Cardassia!
Garak.
All during the years of my exile
I imagined what it would
be like to come home.
I even thought of living
in this house again
with Mila...
but now she's dead
and this house is about to be reduced
to a pile of rubble.
-My Cardassia is gone.
-Then fight for a new Cardassia.
( explosion )
I have an even better reason, Commander.
Revenge.
That works, too.
Oh!
I rid myself of the Prophets
and shed a lifetime of hypocrisy.
I've never seen you look so radiant.
I feel like a young woman
waiting for my lover to sweep me away.
Do you give yourself willingly
to the Pah-wraiths?
-With all my heart.
-Then call to them.
Bring me the book.
Meek rak dorrah Pah-wran.
Yelim cha ono Kosst Amojan...
shay ta-hel ter-rah
no'vala de-ram...
Sisko to Bashir. Report.
Three dead, eight wounded,
four of them critically.
SISKO: Doctor, I need every able-bodied
crewman at their post.
I won't keep anybody here
a second longer than I have to, sir.
Put him over here, will you?
She did pretty well for a first date
don't you think, Captain?
I'd say she did fine, Ensign.
Mr. Worf.
Sir, phaser banks are fully charged
but we are down to 45 quantum torpedoes.
That'll have to do.
How are you holding up, old man?
All things considered
I think I'd rather be on Risa.
Well... that makes two of us.
Have you seen these reports, Captain?
The Dominion has begun
destroying Cardassian cities.
Millions of people are dying.
NOG: Captain, we're approaching
the Dominion defense perimeter.
Well...
let's see what they have waiting for us.
On screen.
Now we know.
( distant explosions )
-We have a problem.
-Just one?
I'm afraid it's a rather large problem.
The cargo door is made of neutronium.
Then the explosives we brought
aren't even going to make a dent.
-You see the problem.
-What do we do?
I don't know
but I'm through hiding in basements.
I fail to see what is so funny, Garak.
Well, isn't it obvious?
Here we are, ready to storm the castle
willing to sacrifice our lives
in the noble effort
to slay the Dominion beast in its lair...
( Kira and Garak laughing )
we can't even get inside the gates.
Maybe... maybe...
we could go up to the door, and...
and ask the Jem'Hadar to let us in?
Why don't we just have them
send the shape-shifter out to us?
( all laughing )
As I said... we have a problem.
But I've come to depend
on having you here at my side.
( distorted voice )
Your advice to the Dominion
has proven invaluable.
( distorted voice )
Very well. If you feel the situation
on the front lines
demands your presence
I will not stand in your way.
Knowing that you'll be leading
our troops into battle
is very reassuring.
( distorted voice )
I still can't help but wonder.
-Wonder what?
-What's under that helmet.
A braver man than you are.
Though I do find the shrillness
of his voice very... tiresome.
Founder, what's wrong?
I'm dying.
That's what's wrong.
Perhaps you should rest for a while
revert to your natural state.
I haven't been able
to change form in weeks.
It's ironic, isn't it?
That I should die as a solid.
You're not going to die. You're a God.
My loyal Weyoun...
the only solid I have ever trusted.
I live only to serve you.
And you have served me well.
I don't mind dying.
It's knowing that my entire race
is dying of the same illness
and there is nothing I can do about it.
I would give my life to save yours.
If only it were that simple.
What if I give myself up
pretend to be your prisoner?
-They'd kill you on sight.
-And us along with you.
( door opening )
The cargo door...
MALE: You're making a terrible mistake!
I'm not a traitor!
Please, just let me speak to the Founder!
No! Wait! No!
( painful groaning )
No!
For Cardassia!
ALL: For Cardassia!
( groans )
( groaning )
Fall back! Fall back!
Keep...
He's dead.
Remember his orders. We stop for nothing.
For Cardassia!
ALL: Cardassia!
We have a security breach.
The guards will deal with it.
Is there a problem?
The guards... there's only a handful
left in the building.
I sent the rest to help
eradicate the Cardassians.
( phasers firing )
You two, get out there
and see that no one
gets through that door.
You stay here in case they fail.
We'll launch a three-pronged attack.
The Romulans and our new Cardassian allies
will engage the Jem'Hadar forces.
The Klingons will target the Breen
and the Federation
will take on the orbital weapon platforms.
Any questions?
When do we go?
As soon as everyone's in position.
It will be a glorious battle.
But a costly one.
Estimates project our casualties
to be as high as 40 percent.
There's no telling how
much higher they'll go
once we send in our ground forces.
The Dominion is beaten and they know it
but they're going to make us pay
for every kilometer of the planet.
Yes, they will.
Let's get on with it.
Godspeed, everyone.
Qapla'.
( phasers firing )
Founder, perhaps we should consider
finding a safer location.
And just where would that be?
( yelling )
Well...
Colonel Kira... what a pleasant surprise.
The pleasure's all mine.
The Federation fleet
has surrounded the planet.
I want you to contact
the Jem'Hadar and the Breen
and you order their ships to stand down.
And order the troops on Cardassia
to do the same.
I will do no such thing.
Tell me, where is my old friend Damar?
Damar is dead.
What a pity.
He died trying to free Cardassia.
What's left of it.
I wish you hadn't done that.
That was Weyoun's last clone.
I was hoping you'd say that.
This war's over. You lost.
Have I?
I think you'll find
that neither the Jem'Hadar
or the Breen will agree
with that assessment.
-They will fight to the last man.
-And what will that accomplish?
Isn't it obvious?
You may win this war, Commander
but I promise you, when it is over
you will have lost
so many ships, so many lives
that your victory will taste
as bitter as defeat.
We're glad to find you
in one piece, Commander.
Very glad.
SISKO: What's your status?
Only three of us
made it to the briefing room.
What about Damar?
He's dead.
Is your position secure?
I don't think the Jem'Hadar will attack.
They won't risk endangering the Founder
and she's in pretty bad shape.
She just sits at her desk
deteriorating.
If she dies before ordering
the Jem'Hadar to surrender...
Then they will fight to the last man.
Captain,
I should beam down there.
The Founder will speak to me.
I can reason with her.
You haven't had much success
with her in the past.
It's worth a try.
Think of the lives it could save.
Very well.
Commander,
tell the Founder that Odo
is going to pay her a visit.
Tarna pur-ono ull-kess Pah-wran.
Lano ka'la bo'shar lanu.
After you.
I'm honored.
Now you.
Why?
The Pah-wraiths demand a sacrifice
someone worthy of them.
Who better than you?
I offer you this life as nourishment
to feed your hunger
to fuel the fires that will set you free.
Kosst Amojan, I am yours, now and forever!
( whir of active transport )
Nerys...
-It's been a while.
-Yes.
Watch yourself. I don't trust her.
But you trust me?
Of course.
That's all I need to know.
Constable.
Garak.
You're looking well, Odo.
Thank you for seeing me.
It's always good to see you...
but I have no intention
of surrendering my forces.
It would be a sign of weakness on my part
an invitation to the solids
to cross into the Gamma Quadrant
and destroy the Great Link.
Believe me, I'm well aware
that the Federation has its flaws
but a desire for conquest
isn't one of them.
And what of the Klingons and the Romulans?
Can you make that claim for them, too?
The Klingon and Romulan Empires
are in no shape to wage
war against anyone.
Besides, the Federation wouldn't allow it.
The Dominion has spent the last two years
trying to destroy the Federation
and now you're asking me
to put our fate in their hands?
Yes.
I can't do that, Odo.
-I don't have your faith in the solids.
-But perhaps I can change your mind.
Link with me.
Odo, what are you doing?
I'm afraid I can't link with you, Odo.
My disease prevents me from changing form.
If we link, I believe I can cure you.
That's a very bad idea, Constable.
I agree.
Nerys, I know what I'm doing.
Please, take my hand.
And if you cure me,
what will you ask in return?
All I ask is that you link with me.
I'm warning you, Odo.
Nerys...
Garak, put down your weapon.
I don't think so.
I said put it down.
Move aside, Odo.
That won't be necessary... will it?
If you will stand aside
I'll order the Jem'Hadar to cease fire.
I suggest we secure her
in a containment field.
ODO: Don't worry, Garak.
She won't try to escape.
She's agreed to stand trial
and accept responsibility
for what she's done.
I would've thought she'd insist
on going back to the Gamma Quadrant
-to cure her people.
-There's no need for that.
I'm going in her place.
For how long?
Nerys...
it's time I rejoined the Great Link.
This is a moment worth savoring.
To victory...
hard fought
and well earned.
What's wrong?
Suddenly, I'm not thirsty.
Neither am I.
Before you waste too many tears
remember... these are Cardassians
lying dead at your feet.
Bajorans would call this...
poetic justice.
That doesn't mean I have to drink
a toast over their bodies.
( bloodwine splattering )
Humans...
( speaking Klingon )
Eight hundred million dead.
And casualty reports still coming in.
Well, aren't you going
to congratulate me, Doctor?
My exile is now officially over.
I've returned home...
or rather, to what's left of it.
Listen, I-I know that this must seem--
You know, some may say
that we've gotten just what we deserved.
After all, we're not entirely innocent,
are we?
And I'm not just speaking
of the Bajoran occupation.
No, our whole history
is one of arrogant aggression.
We've collaborated with the Dominion
betrayed the entire Alpha Quadrant.
Oh, no, no, there's no doubt about it.
We're guilty as charged.
You and I both know that the Cardassians
are a strong people.
-They'll survive. Cardassia will survive.
-Oh, please, Doctor.
Spare me your insufferable
Federation optimism.
Of course, it'll survive...
but not as the Cardassia I knew.
We had a rich and ancient culture.
Our literature, music,
art was second to none.
And now...
so much of it is...
lost.
So many of our best people...
our most gifted minds...
-I'm sorry, Garak. I didn't mean...
-Oh, it's... it's quite all right, Doctor.
You've been such a good friend.
I'm going to miss our lunches together.
-I'm sure we'll see each other again.
-I'd like to think so.
But one can never say.
We live in uncertain times.
The war between
the Dominion and the Federation Alliance
is now over.
Four hundred years ago,
a victorious general
spoke the following words
at the end of another costly war,
"Today the guns are silent.
A great tragedy has ended.
We have known the bitterness of defeat
and the exultation of triumph
and from both we have learned
there can be no going back.
We must move forward
to preserve in peace
what we've won in war."
It's up to you now, Odo.
-You're coming to Vic's tonight, right?
-I will be there.
But I will not dance.
Who's asking?
-SISKO: Commander Worf.
-Captain.
-Can you spare a moment?
-WORF: Yes, sir.
We've been discussing
your plans for the future.
I was not aware I had any plans.
Commander, how would you feel
about being named
Federation Ambassador to Kronos?
I am not a diplomat.
And I am not a politician
but sometimes fate plays
cruel tricks on us, Worf.
Come. Kronos needs you.
And what's more, I need you.
You helped him become Chancellor.
Can't very well turn your back on him now.
Well, my first loyalty is to you, Captain.
Thank you, Mr. Worf.
I'll probably regret this in the morning
but, if it's what you want...
then by all means.
It has been a great honor
serving with you.
The honor is mine.
I accept.
Excellent.
An ambassador
who'll go targ hunting with me.
Well... perhaps being Chancellor
won't be so bad after all.
Congratulations, Worf.
When will you be going?
Soon.
You could come back, you know...
once you've cured your people.
I could.
But you're not going to do that.
( sighing ) Nerys...
you know my feelings for you
will never change...
but I have to do this. My people need me.
They need to know what I know
to learn what I've learned...
from living among solids.
It's the only way
they'll ever learn to trust you.
You don't have to justify
your decision, Odo.
There's just one thing...
Anything.
I'd like to take you
back to your home world.
I'd like that.
I'd like that very much.
Hey... pally.
If you're here for another game
of "Go Fish"
I'm a little busy right now.
Actually, I'm here
for the "End of the war,
good-bye to Chief O'Brien, good-bye to Odo
good-bye to Worf party."
At the bar.
No, seriously, Miles.
You know, I envy you,
going back to Earth...
chance to enjoy paradise again.
Any idea where you're going to live?
No, Keiko and I are still mulling
over a few possibilities.
Have you ever considered Minsk?
I don't think that's on our list.
New Orleans is a gorgeous city.
I've heard great things about Paris.
Minsk.
Jadzia loved Rio.
Well, you've certainly
got a lot of choices.
Yeah. Too many, hmm?
WORF: Minsk.
Well, wherever you decide to go
I'm sure that you and Keiko
will both be very happy.
Listen, Julian, I know Earth
isn't exactly around the corner
-but I still expect you to visit.
-I intend to.
Yeah.
You and me, take a little trip to Texas.
Standing side by side
in front of the Alamo.
The real Alamo, hmm?
See? It's going to be great.
Absolutely.
I don't see how great it would be.
Earth's nothing more than
a rotating ball of boredom.
If you ask me,
you'd be better off staying here.
And that goes for you and Worf as well.
Don't tell me you're getting
sentimental, Quark.
Me?
Not a chance.
I just don't like change.
You better get used to it.
Things are going to be pretty
different around here now.
To the best crew any Captain ever had.
This may be the last time
we're all together...
but no matter what the future holds...
no matter how far we travel
a part of us... a very important part,
will always remain here...
on Deep Space 9.
Hear, hear! Cheers.
VIC: Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight is a very special night
for some friends of mine.
They've been together a long time.
( soft jazz playing )
But like the man said
"Nothing lasts forever."
So, gang...
this one's from the heart.
Someday
When I'm awfully low
When the world is cold
I will feel a glow
Just thinking of you
And the way you look tonight
( trumpet solo )
You are lovely
With your smile so warm
And your cheeks so soft
There is nothing for me
But to love you
Just the way you look
Tonight
( saxophone solo )
With each word
Your tenderness grows
Tearing my fear
Apart
And that laugh
That wrinkles your nose
Touches my
Foolish heart
( saxophone solo )
Someday
When I'm awfully low
( trumpet solo )
When the world is cold
I will feel a glow
Just thinking of you
And the way you look
Tonight
WINN: Dorrah tolka bretri Pah-wran.
Kosst Amojan, come to me.
I await you.
( screams )
No!
( slow jazz playing )
Ben, what's wrong?
I understand now.
Understand what?
What I have to do. What I was meant to do.
Kasidy, I have to go.
Go where?
-To Bajor, to the fire caves.
-I'll go with you.
No...
I have to do this alone.
( Dukat laughs )
Did you really think
the Pah-wraiths would choose you
as their Emissary?
( laughs )
Soon the Pah-wraiths
will burn across Bajor...
the Celestial Temple...
the Alpha Quadrant. Can you picture it?
An entire universe... set in flames...
to burn for all eternity.
The Prophets have sent me a gift.
Their beloved Emissary sent forth
like an avenging angel
to slay the demon.
I should have known
the demon would be you.
Go on... kill me if you can.
( Dukat laughing )
You'll have to do better
than that, Captain.
( Dukat laughs )
It's just too easy.
That's it. Come closer. That's it.
Now bow to me.
I said bow.
( struggling ) You are pathetic.
Then why are you the one on your knees?
First the Dominion, now the Pah-wraiths.
You have a talent
for picking the losing sides.
Benjamin, please,
we've know each other too long.
And since this is the last time
we will ever be together
let's try to speak honestly.
We've both had our victories
and our defeats.
Now it's time to resolve our differences
and face the ultimate truth.
I've won, Benjamin.
You've lost.
The Pah-wraiths
will never conquer anything,
not Bajor... not the Celestial Temple
and certainly not the Alpha Quadrant.
And who's going to stop us?
I am!
You can't even stand up.
WINN: Then I'll stop you.
Are you still here?
Emissary, the book!
Farewell, Adami.
( screams )
( yelling )
( heartbeat thudding )
Sarah?
Are you here?
What happened?
The Emissary has completed his task.
But the Pah-wraiths...
You've returned them to their prison
within the fire caves.
The book was the key, wasn't it?
To a door that can never be opened again.
And Dukat... is he dead?
He's where he belongs,
with the Pah-wraiths.
Your time of trial has ended.
You need to rest now.
Oh, I intend to as soon as I return
to Deep Space 9.
That won't be necessary.
You're with us now.
We found the Captain's runabout
orbiting Bajor.
But when we scanned the fire caves
there was no sign of him.
Tarkalian tea. Soothing.
Better keep it coming.
You're not calling off
the search yet, are you?
Not until we find your father.
What about the Kendra Province,
where he bought that land?
Maybe he went there for some reason.
Colonel Kira and Chief O'Brien
have completed another scan of the planet.
As far as they can tell, he is not there.
Something's happened to Ben...
something bad.
I can feel it.
The Prophets warned us.
( whispering voices, heartbeat thudding )
Hello?
Is anyone here?
Ben? Is that you?
SISKO: Kasidy...
Oh, Ben.
Oh, I've been so worried about you.
Where are we?
The Celestial Temple.
This is scaring me. Let's go home.
I can't. Not now.
Why not?
Oh, God.
This is it, isn't it?
The sorrow that the Prophets
warned us about.
It's difficult to explain.
It's not linear.
What isn't?
My life...
my destiny...
The Prophets saved me, Kasidy.
I'm their Emissary
and they still have a great deal
for me to do.
But first...
there is much to learn...
things only the Prophets can teach me.
When will you be back?
It's hard to say.
Maybe a year...
maybe...
yesterday.
But I will be back.
And I will be waiting.
Kas, can you hear me?
You seemed pretty far away for a second.
I was talking to your father.
Are you sure you want to leave
without saying good-bye?
I'm sure.
I've never been good at good-byes.
There are going to be a lot of people
that are disappointed.
If they don't know
how I feel about them now
a few parting words
won't make the difference.
Aha! I knew it.
When I saw the two of you slip out
I said to myself
"That no-good, misanthropic
cantankerous changeling is trying
to sneak off the station
without anyone noticing."
That was the idea.
Well, it's not going to happen, is it?
Apparently not.
So...
now that I'm here...
is there something you want to say to me?
Such as...?
Such as...
"Good-bye. You certainly were
a worthy adversary."
Or maybe something
with the words "mutual respect" in it.
No.
No? What do you mean, no?
I mean no.
I have nothing I want to say to you.
Are you telling me
that after all these years
after all we've been through
you're not even going
to say good-bye to me?
That's right.
Nerys... I'll be on the runabout.
( scoffs )
Don't take it hard, Quark.
Hard?
What are you talking about?
That man loves me.
Couldn't you see?
It was written all over his back.
The Link...
it's so different.
They're dying.
You should go to them.
Yes.
Nerys...
please, tell everyone I'll miss them.
Even Quark?
Even Quark.
But most of all...
I know.
Odo...
You always said I looked good in a tuxedo.
You do.
Then this is the way
I want you to remember me.
I'll never forget you.
Good-bye, Nerys.
The duty roster, Colonel.
Nice work.
Congratulations
on your promotion, Lieutenant.
Thank you, sir.
I guess putting me in for a promotion
was one of Captain Sisko's
last official acts.
I'm sure he's very proud of you, Nog.
I'd like to think so, sir.
Now, about the cargo inventories...
I'll get right on it.
You know, the thing is,
the apoptosis is really
just part of the normal
cardiac renewal process.
What do you think?
I think that after dinner tonight
we should go to Quark's
spend some time in the holosuite.
Oh... I'd like a trip to Vegas.
Actually, I was thinking about the Alamo.
-We can't go there.
-Why not?
Because that's what Miles and I... did.
But I do have a new program,
the Battle of Thermopylae.
Do you know it?
Well, it's about a force of Spartans
led by King Leonidas
who defend a mountain pass
against a vast army of Persians.
What happens then?
Well, for two days
the Spartans lead a heroic struggle.
Until they're wiped out.
Yes.
How'd you know?
Lucky guess.
I take it we'll be the Spartans.
-Fighting to the last man.
-Just like the Alamo.
Exactly.
Have you talked to a Counselor
about these annihilation fantasies?
Do you think I should?
Mm-hmm. I'll set up a session
for you tomorrow.
What about tonight?
Tonight, we defend the pass.
Don't worry.
It's guaranteed to grow hair within a week
though if you ask me
that dome of yours is hairy enough.
Besides, hasn't there been enough change
around here already?
KIRA: Quark!
You mind explaining this?
Oh, uh, that's, um...
this week's betting pool.
You're taking bets
on who's going to be the new Kai?
It's a wide open field.
Just between you and me
the smart money is on Vedek Ungtae.
Ah... well, just between you and me
all bets are off.
What are you talking about?
As of this moment,
betting pools of any kind
are illegal on this station.
I catch someone placing a bet
I put you in a holding cell for 15 days.
Is that clear?
Fifteen days?
Can I bring my own pillow?
Quark...
It's clear, it's clear.
Better be.
( sighs ) It's like I said,
the more things change,
the more they stay the same.