male narrator:
THIS IS MICHAEL BLUTH.
FOR 10 YEARS, HE'S WORKED
FOR HIS FATHER'S COMPANY,
WAITING TO BE MADE A PARTNER.
AND RIGHT NOW, HE'S HAPPY.
THIS IS MICHAEL'S MOTHER.
- LOOK WHAT THEY'VE DONE,
MICHAEL.
narrator:
SHE ISN'T HAPPY.
- LOOK WHAT THE HOMOSEXUALS
HAVE DONE TO ME.
- YOU CAN'T JUST COMB THAT OUT
AND RESET IT?
narrator:
CURRENTLY, SHE'S UPSET
THAT HER HUSBAND'S
RETIREMENT PARTY
IS BEING UPSTAGED BY A GROUP
OF GAY PROTESTERS.
[together]
WE'RE HERE. WE'RE QUEER.
WE WANT TO GET MARRIED
ON THE OCEAN.
- EVERYTHING THEY DO
IS SO DRAMATIC AND FLAMBOYANT.
IT JUST MAKES ME
WANT TO SET MYSELF ON FIRE.
- [sighs]
GOOD GRIEF, MOTHER.
NOT ALL HOMOSEXUALS
ARE FLAMBOY--
OH, MY GOD.
I HAVE THE EXACT SAME BLOUSE.
narrator: THIS IS MICHAEL'S
TWIN SISTER, LINDSAY.
- I LIKE IT BETTER ON HIM.
narrator: AS A YOUTHFUL ACT
OF DEFIANCE,
LINDSAY MARRIED THIS MAN.
THEY MOVED TO BOSTON,
WHERE THEY'VE BECOME CELEBRATED
FOR THEIR WINE AND CHEESE
FUND-RAISERS.
- OH, NO.
I'M COMPLETELY STUFFED.
narrator: MICHAEL AND HIS SISTER
HAVEN'T SPOKEN IN A YEAR.
NEITHER HAS ACKNOWLEDGED THIS.
AND THIS IS GOB,
MICHAEL'S OLDEST BROTHER.
- SO THIS IS
THE MAGIC TRICK, HUH?
- ILLUSION, MICHAEL.
A TRICK IS SOMETHING
A WHORE DOES FOR MONEY.
OR CANDY.
narrator: GOB RECENTLY STARTED
THE ALLIANCE OF MAGICIANS,
AN ORGANIZATION THAT BLACKBALLS
ANY PERFORMER
WHO REVEALS A MAGICIAN'S SECRET.
AND FINALLY,
THERE'S BUSTER...
- HEY, BUSTER.
narrator: THE YOUNGEST
OF MICHAEL'S SIBLINGS.
- YOU KNOW, YOU DON'T NEED
TO DO THAT, BUDDY.
IT'S OKAY.
narrator:
THANKS TO THE FAMILY'S LARGES,
BUSTER HAS STUDIED EVERYTHING.
FROM NATIVE AMERICAN
TRIBAL CEREMONIES...
TO CARTOGRAPHY, THE MAPPING
OF UNCHARTED TERRITORIES.
- HASN'T EVERYTHING ALREADY
SORT OF BEEN DISCOVERED, THOUGH,
BY, LIKE, MAGELLAN AND CORTEZ...
- OH, YEAH, YEAH.
- ALL THOSE FOLKS?
- THOSE GUYS DID
A PRETTY GOOD JOB,
BUT THERE'S STILL,
YOU KNOW--
narrator: HE ALSO SUFFERS
FROM CRIPPLING PANIC ATTACKS.
YES, THIS IS HIS FAMILY.
SO WHY IS MICHAEL SO HAPPY?
BECAUSE HE'S DECIDED TO NEVER
SPEAK TO THESE PEOPLE AGAIN.
MICHAEL WAS FEELING MORE
GENEROUS ABOUT HIS FAMILY
ON THE MORNING
OF THE BOAT PARTY.
- WHAT COMES BEFORE ANYTHING?
WHAT HAVE WE ALWAYS SAID
IS THE MOST IMPORTANT THING?
- BREAKFAST.
- FAMILY.
- FAMILY, RIGHT.
I THOUGHT YOU MEANT
OF THE THINGS YOU EAT.
narrator: THIS IS MICHAEL'S SON,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
I MEAN, WE HAVE MADE NOTHING
BUT SACRIFICES FOR THIS FAMILY,
AND TONIGHT
IT ALL PAYS OFF, MY BOY.
TONIGHT YOUR GRANDDAD
MAKES ME PARTNER.
narrator:
TO PROVE HIS DEDICATION
TO THE FAMILY BUSINESS,
MICHAEL HAS DECIDED
TO LIVE HERE
IN THE MODEL UNIT OF HIS
FATHER'S LATEST HOUSING TRACT.
THE GUYS LIVE IN THE ATTIC
SO THAT THE HOUSE
CAN STILL FUNCTION
AS A PRISTINE SELLING TOOL.
- AND WHEN I DO GET
THAT PROMOTION,
I'LL FINALLY BE ABLE
TO GET YOU WHAT YOU DESERVE,
LIKE A REAL HOME.
- THIS IS A REAL HOME.
- NO, IT'S NOT.
IT'S A FAKE HOME, SON.
YOU WANT THE LOOPS
OR THE FLAKES TODAY?
narrator: THE GUYS THEN HEADED
DOWN TO BALBOA ISLAND
SO GEORGE MICHAEL COULD WORK
AT THE FROZEN BANANA STAND
HIS GRANDFATHER STARTED IN 1953.
- BANANAS.
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
WAS MEETING HIS BROTHER GOB,
HOPING TO DISCUSS
HIS FATHER'S BOAT PARTY.
- DO YOU HAVE YOUR CHECK
FOR YOUR SHARE OF THE PARTY?
- YOU KNOW, I SORT OF THOUGHT
MY CONTRIBUTION
COULD BE A MAGIC SHOW.
- OH, THAT'S PERFECT, GOB.
- THANK YOU.
- OR WAIT A MINUTE.
I JUST REMEMBERED SOMETHING.
DAD'S RETIRING, NOT TURNING SIX.
- HEY, COME ON.
I JUST BOUGHT THIS NEW ILLUSION
CALLED THE AZTEC TOMB.
IT COST, LIKE, 18 GRAND.
I'M GONNA DO IT ON THE BOAT.
WHAT DO YOU CARE?
CAN'T YOU JUST CHARGE
THE PARTY TO THE COMPANY?
- NO,
IT'S NOT A BUSINESS EXPENSE.
- SO WHAT?
LINDSAY'S BEEN STAYING
AT THE FOUR SEASONS FOR A MONTH.
SHE'S PROBABLY
CHARGING THE COMPANY.
- LINDSAY'S BEEN
IN TOWN FOR A MONTH?
- I DON'T THINK SO.
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS UPSET TO HEAR THIS,
SO HE WENT TO DISCUSS IT
WITH HIS MOTHER.
- MOM. MOTHER.
GIVE ME
YOUR COMPANY CHECKBOOK.
YOU'RE CUT OFF.
- MICHAEL, LOOK.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENED TO MY FOX.
SOMEONE CUT OFF
HIS LITTLE FOOT.
IS IT--IS IT NOTICEABLE?
- WELL,
YOU'VE GOTTA REMEMBER,
YOU'RE GONNA BE ALL
SPLATTERED IN RED PAINT.
THAT'S GONNA
DISTRACT THE EYE.
I DON'T WANT YOU CHARGING
ANY MORE
OF YOUR PERSONAL EXPENSES
TO THE COMPANY.
- WELL, I HAD TO PAY
FOR THE AZTEC TOMB.
GOB SAYS IT'S A CAREER-MAKER.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
THE COMPANY PAID
FOR THE AZTEC TOMB?
THAT'S GREAT.
WELL, I WAS TALKING
ABOUT LINDSAY, OKAY?
YOU PUT HER IN
A FIVE-STAR HOTEL
ON TOP OF WHICH YOU DIDN'T EVEN
TELL ME THAT SHE WAS IN TOWN.
- IF YOU'RE SAYING
I PLAY FAVORITES, YOU'RE WRONG.
I LOVE ALL MY CHILDREN EQUALLY.
I DON'T CARE FOR GOB.
GOOD GRIEF; I DIPPED INTO
THE KITTY A COUPLE OF TIMES.
YOU SHOULD BE FOCUSED
ON TONIGHT.
DAD'S MAKING A BIG ANNOUNCEMENT.
- YEAH?
I KNEW IT.
IT'S ABOUT ME, ISN'T IT?
I WONDER HOW I CAN TALK YOU
OUT OF EVER MAKING
THAT FACE AGAIN.
- MICHAEL.
- TOBIAS.
- HOW ARE YOU?
[laughs]
- GOOD, GOOD.
HOW'S YOUR JOB SEARCH COMIN'?
- IT'S GOOD.
IT'S GOING TO BE GOOD.
I'M HOPING THE UNIVERSE
PROVIDES A PATH FOR ME.
narrator: TOBIAS RECENTLY LOST
HIS MEDICAL LICENSE
FOR ADMINISTERING C.P.R. TO
A PERSON WHO, AS IT TURNED OUT,
WAS NOT HAVING A HEART ATTACK.
- MAYBE YOU'LL BE INSPIRED
BY THE BOAT PARTY TONIGHT,
START A CAREER AS A PIRATE.
- I HAVEN'T PACKED FOR THAT.
- COULDN'T FIND A THING.
- LINDSAY.
- MICHAEL.
- HOW WAS YOUR FLIGHT?
- GREAT. GREAT.
WE JUST GOT IN...
- HE KNOWS.
- A MONTH AGO.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I'VE BEEN MEANING TO CALL YOU.
I REALLY HAVE.
- REALLY?
- IT'S JUST BEEN VERY BUSY.
- UGH. IT'S BEEN CRAZY.
- WE JUST HAD AN AMAZING
FUND-RAISER FOR HOOP.
- HOOP?
- MY ANTI-CIRCUMCISION
MOVEMENT.
I THINK IT LOOKS FRIGHTENING
WHEN IT'S CUT OFF.
IT'S A DOBERMAN.
LET IT HAVE ITS EARS.
- HMM.
- BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
WE BROUGHT IN OVER $40,000.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU SAVED ENOUGH
SKIN TO MAKE 10 NEW BOYS.
- WELL, MOST OF THAT MONEY
WAS FROM THE BLUTH COMPANY.
- [clears throat]
- I MEAN, HOW...
ARE YOU?
- STILL GOOD.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU GUYS HAVE HAD YOUR HANDS
IN THE COMPANY COFFER FOR YEARS.
BUT STARTING TOMORROW, THERE IS
GOING TO BE A NEW BOSS IN TOWN,
AND YOU'RE ALL GONNA HAVE TO
START FENDING FOR YOURSELVES.
YOU'RE ALL GONNA FINALLY FEEL
THAT SWEET STING OF SWEAT
IN YOUR EYES AS...
[drum pounding]
BUSTER, YOU CAN'T DO THAT
ON THE BALCONY, BUDDY?
- MOM SAYS IT'S TOO WINDY.
- WHO COULD'VE DONE THIS?
narrator: WHILE MICHAEL WAS
GETTING FED UP WITH HIS FAMILY,
GEORGE MICHAEL WAS FINALLY
GETTING TO KNOW THEM.
- UM, YEAH,
I BOUGHT A FROZEN BANANA,
AND WHEN I BIT INTO IT,
I FOUND THIS.
- LOOKS LIKE A FOOT.
- IT TASTED LIKE A FOOT,
WHICH I DIDN'T REALLY MIND,
BUT I'M PRETTY SURE
I SAID, "NO NUTS."
- HEY, YOU'RE MY COUSIN,
AREN'T YOU?
- MAYBE.
narrator: THIS IS GEORGE
MICHAEL'S COUSIN, MAEBY.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU DIDN'T RECOGNIZE ME.
- WE NEVER SEE YOU.
WE NEVER SEE ANYBODY
IN OUR FAMILY.
- I KNOW.
IT'S OUR PARENTS' FAULTS.
- WE SHOULD TEACH THEM A LESSON.
- [laughs]
YEAH, RIGHT.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
- I SHOULD GO
TO MY MOM TONIGHT
AND BE LIKE,
"I MET THE CUTEST GUY,"
AND THEN SHE'LL SEE YOU
AND ME TOTALLY MAKING OUT.
- [laughs]
YEAH.
BUT--BUT NOT REALLY, RIGHT?
- IT'S PERFECT.
SHE'D FREAK OUT.
AND I'D BE LIKE, "MOM, IF WE SAW
EACH OTHER MORE OFTEN,
THIS WOULDN'T HAPPEN."
- BUT WE'RE COUSINS.
- THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT FUNNY.
- BUT ISN'T IT AGAINST THE LAW?
- COME ON, GEORGE MICHAEL.
narrator: TOBIAS, NOW BELIEVING
THE BOAT PARTY
TO BE PIRATE-THEMED...
YOU LOOK LIKE A PIRATE.
narrator: BEGAN SEARCHING
THROUGH HIS WIFE'S LUGGAGE
FOR AN OUTFIT.
- I SHOULD SAY SO.
LOOK AT THE BLOUSE, SIR.
narrator:
THEN, MISTAKING A GROUP
OF GARISHLY DRESSED MEN
FOR PIRATES,
TOBIAS BOARDED A VAN
FULL OF HOMOSEXUALS.
SOON HE WAS UNWITTINGLY
PART OF A PROTEST
AGAINST THE LOCAL YACHT CLUB.
- HOW ARE YOU?
- OH, MY GOD.
I HAVE THE EXACT SAME BLOUSE.
- I LIKE IT BETTER ON HIM.
narrator: AND MICHAEL'S
BIG MOMENT FINALLY CAME.
I GIVE YOU THE NEW C.E.O.
FOR THE BLUTH COMPANY,
CERTAINLY THE SMARTEST BLUTH,
MY FAVORITE BLUTH,
AND THE, UH, SEXIEST CREATURE
I HAVE EVER LAID EYES ON,
MY LOVELY WIFE, LUCILLE.
- [squeals]
[cheers and applause]
- MOM.
- [squeals]
- [singing]
LOVE.
LOVE WILL KEEP US TOGETHER.
- SORRY.
IT'S NOT THE RIGHT TIME.
- [singing]
THINK OF ME, BABE, WHENEVER
SOME SWEET-TALKIN' GIRL
COMES ALONG, SINGIN'...
- I'M NOT GONNA LIE
TO YOU, MICHAEL.
THIS IS GREAT NEWS FOR HOOP.
- [singing]
NOT MUCH MORE I'M ASKIN' FOR
FREE
FREE AT LAST
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT FREEDOM
FREEDOM
- HEY.
- YOU OKAY?
- YOU AND I,
WE'VE WAITED LONG ENOUGH.
IT'S TIME TO MOVE ON.
ALL RIGHT?
- I GUESS WE'RE GONNA SEE
YOU GUYS EVEN LESS NOW.
- I TOLD YOU.
WE SHOULD'VE TAUGHT THEM
A LESSON.
- LINDSAY, I WANT YOU
IN THIS PICTURE. COME ON.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S SEE SOME SMILES, PEOPLE.
IT'S A--IT'S A PARTY,
NOT A SHAREHOLDERS' MEETING.
[sirens wailing]
- ARE THOSE POLICE BOATS?
[rimshot]
NO, I'M SERIOUS.
I THINK THEY ARE POLICE BOATS.
- PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
- I KNEW IT WAS AGAINST THE LAW.
- THAT'S THE SECURITIES
AND EXCHANGE COMMISSION.
- THEY HAVE BOATS?
- GIVE ME A CELL PHONE.
- LINDSAY, BUSTER,
UP TO THE BRIDGE.
COME ON, BUSTER.
ALMIGHTY GOOD GRIEF.
- DELORES, LISTEN TO ME.
EMPTY THE ACCOUNT.
WHY ARE YOU CRYING?
- OUT OF MY WAY.
OUT. OUT. OUT.
LINDSAY, TAKE THE WHEEL.
BUSTER, FIND US A CHANNEL
TO THE OCEAN.
- GEE, I DON'T HAVE ANY
MAPPING EQUIPMENT WITH ME.
- YOU'VE HAD $80,000
WORTH OF CARTOGRAPHY LESSONS.
GET US A CHANNEL TO THE OCEAN.
- OKAY. OKAY. OKAY.
- CAN YOU HEAR ME NOW?
- OBVIOUSLY, THIS BLUE PART
HERE IS THE LAND.
AND THAT WOULD MEAN--
OH, BUSTER, BUSTER,
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
- SHREDDER. NO. SAVE IT.
SAVE IT. SHREDDER.
- PLEASE, DON'T LEAVE US NOW,
BUSTER, PLEASE.
- GET IN THE TOMB,
THE AZTEC TOMB.
- HOLD ON. I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR YOUR MAGIC TRICKS.
- ILLUSIONS, DAD.
YOU DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR MY ILLUSIONS.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
WHY ARE YOU SO ANGRY?
- LOOK, JUST STAY IN THE BOX.
I'LL MAKE YOU DISAPPEAR.
narrator: THE BLUTH FAMILY
DOMINATED THE NEWS THAT NIGHT.
- BLUTH DEVELOPMENT COMPANY
PRESIDENT GEORGE BLUTH
WAS ARRESTED TONIGHT
FOR DEFRAUDING INVESTORS
AND USING THE COMPANY
AS HIS PERSONAL PIGGY BANK.
MORE INTRIGUE
ON THE HIGH SEAS TONIGHT
AS DOZENS OF LOCAL PIRATES
WERE ARRESTED
FOR PROTESTING THE YACHT CLUB'S
DISCRIMINATORY POLICIES.
narrator: EVEN MICHAEL'S BROTHER
GOB MADE THE NEWS.
- IT WAS MR. BLUTH'S SON, GOB,
A PART-TIME MAGICIAN,
WHO HID HIS FATHER HERE
IN THE AZTEC TOMB
BY PUSHING ON THIS
PIVOTING PANEL--
- I HAVE TO THINK THE ALLIANCE
IS GONNA FROWN ON THIS.
- PERHAPS A GOOD TRICK
FOR A HUMAN,
BUT THE DOGS FOUND HIM
ALMOST INSTANTLY.
- FREE AT LAST, DARLINGS.
- I'M ALL RIGHT.
- THANK GOD.
- OH, WHAT AN ADVENTURE.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
BUSTER, DON'T DO THAT.
WHAT AN ADVENTURE, GANG.
I THOUGHT THAT
THE HOMOSEXUALS WERE PIRATES,
BUT IT TURNS OUT THAT
MOST OF THEM WERE ACTORS
IN THE LOCAL THEATER.
[chuckles]
YOU'RE RIGHT, THOUGH.
IT IS AMAZING.
I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR THE UNIVERSE
TO PROVIDE A PATH FOR ME,
AND--
AND I THINK IT HAS.
- YOU'RE GAY?
- NO. NO.
NO, I'M NOT--I'M NOT GAY.
NO, LINDSAY, HOW MANY
TIMES MUST WE HAVE THIS--
NO,
I WANT TO BE AN ACTOR.
[chuckles]
- OKAY, GUYS. UM,
THEY ARE GONNA
KEEP DAD IN PRISON
AT LEAST UNTIL THIS
GETS ALL SORTED OUT.
ALSO, THE ATTORNEY SAID THEY'RE
GONNA HAVE TO PUT A HALT
ON THE COMPANY'S
EXPENSE ACCOUNT.
[all gasp]
INTERESTING;
I WOULD HAVE EXPECTED THAT
AFTER THE,
"KEEPING DAD IN JAIL."
- YOU KNOW, MICHAEL, DAD DID
NAME MOM AS HIS SUCCESSOR.
- AND I'M PUTTING BUSTER
IN CHARGE.
- THAT'S A GOOD CHOICE.
- BUSTER?
THE GUY WHO THOUGHT THAT
THE BLUE ON THE MAP WAS LAND?
- HE'S HAD BUSINESS CLASSES.
- WA-WA-WA-WAIT,
18TH-CENTURY AGRARIAN BUSINESS.
BUT I GUESS IT'S ALL
THE SAME PRINCIPLES.
ARE YOU AT ALL CONCERNED
ABOUT AN UPRISING?
- THAT'S IT.
I'M DONE.
I'M SICK AND TIRED OF THE GREED
AND THE SELFISHNESS
AND ALL THE TAKING.
FORGET IT.
I'VE GOT A SON TO THINK ABOUT.
AND, LINDSAY, BY THE WAY,
I EXPECTED THIS FROM THEM,
BECAUSE THEY'RE
COMPLETELY OBLIVIOUS.
BUT YOU--
YOU SHOULD KNOW BETTER.
narrator:
IN THE DAYS THAT FOLLOWED,
LINDSAY HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO CHECK HER FAMILY
OUT OF THE HOTEL
EARLIER THAN PLANNED.
AND HER HUSBAND
STARTED LOOKING FOR WORK.
- MY NAME IS DR. TOBIAS FUNKE.
I WAS CHIEF RESIDENT
OF PSYCHIATRY AT MASS GENERAL
FOR TWO YEARS,
AND I DID MY FELLOWSHIP
IN PSYCHOLINGUISTICS AT M.I.T.
AND THIS IS
"I'M A BAD, BAD MAN"
FROM "ANNIE GET YOUR GUN."
[upbeat piano music]
[singing]
I-I--I'M--
narrator: LUCILLE WAS
FINDING IT DIFFICULT
TO GO ABOUT HER DAILY LIFE.
- THE S.E.C. IS MAKING HIM OUT
TO BE SOME KIND OF MASTERMIND,
WHICH--BELIEVE ME--HE'S NOT.
THE MAN CAN BARELY
WORK OUR SHREDDER.
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS ABLE TO SECURE
A JOB WITH A RIVAL HOUSING
COMPANY ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
- WE'LL SET YOU UP IN ARIZONA
IN ONE OF OUR FINEST ESTATES.
- ATTIC OR MAIN HOUSE?
- [laughs]
narrator: AND BUSTER
WAS DISCOVERING
HIS ACADEMIC PURSUITS
DIDN'T FULLY PREPARE HIM
FOR HIS NEW RESPONSIBILITIES.
- HAVE YOU LOOKED
AT THE LATEST FIGURES
ON
THE SUDDEN VALLEY EXPANSION...
VIS-A-VIS THE DEVELOPMENT
VERSUS THE TAX...
- YOU GUYS ARE SO SMART.
- 2% PER ANNUM.
THIS IS A NON-RECOUPABLE...
- WE NEED MICHAEL.
- WE NEED ICE.
- [muffled] MICHAEL.
WE NEED MICHAEL.
narrator: AND SO THE FAMILY
STAGED AN INTERVENTION.
- I'M SORRY.
WHAT EXACTLY
IS THIS INTERVENTION FOR?
- WE NEED YOU TO COME BACK
AND RUN THE BUSINESS.
- OKAY, SO TECHNICALLY IT'S
NOT REALLY AN INTERVENTION.
IT'S MORE OF AN IMPOSITION
IF YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
- WHATEVER YOU WANT TO CALL IT.
- I'D LOVE TO CALL IT
AN IMPOSITION.
- WE'RE IN TROUBLE HERE,
MICHAEL.
AND I CAN'T PERFORM MY MAGIC.
I'M GETTING BLACKBALLED
FROM EVEN THE SMALLER VENUES.
- I'LL BE HONEST.
I'M JUST MORE COMFORTABLE WITH
AN ALLIANCE-APPROVED MAGICIAN.
- [scoffs]
GIVE 'EM A HELL
OF A SHOW, CHAMP.
- [bleep] OFF, TRAITOR.
- CAN YOU BELIEVE THIS?
THEY'RE STILL FIGHTING.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
I'M TEMPTED TO KISS AGAIN
SO WE COULD TEACH 'EM A LESSON.
- WHY WOULD THAT
TEACH THEM A LESSON?
- NO, I MEAN, UH,
TO FREAK THEM OUT.
- YEAH, BUT THAT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
- ISN'T THAT WHAT MAKES
IT FUNNY?
I'M LAUGHING.
GO FISH--UNO--OKAY.
I JUST NEED A DRINK.
- WELL, I'M SORRY.
IT'S JUST TOO LATE.
I'M MOVING TO PHOENIX.
I GOT A JOB.
SOMETHING YOU APPLY FOR,
AND THEN THEY PAY YOU TO, UH--
NEVER MIND; I DON'T
WANT TO RUIN THE SURPRISE.
SO NO HARD FEELINGS.
ADIOS. SAYONARA.
I'LL SEE YOU
WHEN THE FIRST PARENT DIES.
WELL, I'D RATHER BE DEAD
IN CALIFORNIA
THAN ALIVE IN ARIZONA.
[laughter]
- TOUCHE.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, GRAB THE COAT.
- I THINK DAD WOULD REALLY
WANT YOU TO HELP US OUT HERE.
- DAD'S IN JAIL.
HERE WE GO.
- WELL, THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
IS SAY GOOD-BYE TO HIM.
narrator:
IN FACT, MICHAEL HAD NOT SPOKEN
TO HIS FATHER SINCE THE ARREST,
AND HE DECIDED TO GIVE
HIS FATHER THE COURTESY
OF A FORMAL RESIGNATION.
- I QUIT.
- PROBABLY A GOOD CAREER MOVE.
- YOU KNOW, I PARKED IN THE SAME
SPOT FOR THE LAST FIVE YEARS.
I WAS THERE ON TIME
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
- MIKE--
- I WAS SO LOYAL.
I WORKED SO HARD.
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST
PUT ME IN CHARGE?
- MICHAEL, LISTEN TO ME.
THESE GUYS, THE S.E.C.,
THEY'VE BEEN AFTER ME FOR YEARS.
I PUT YOU IN CHARGE,
YOU'RE GONNA BE WEARING
ONE OF THESE JUMPSUITS TOO.
- I COULD'VE HELPED--
- YOU'D BE AN ACCOMPLICE.
NO.
IT HAD TO BE YOUR MOM.
THEY CANNOT ARREST
A HUSBAND AND WIFE
FOR THE SAME CRIME.
- YEAH, I DON'T THINK
THAT THAT'S TRUE, DAD.
- REALLY?
I GOT THE WORST
[bleep] ATTORNEYS.
narrator:
WITH MICHAEL LEAVING TOWN,
LINDSAY DECIDED
TO TAKE INVENTORY
OF THE FAMILY'S
LAST REMAINING ASSET:
THEIR MODEL HOME.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- PACKING UP.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WELL,
JUST LOOKING FOR...YOU...
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO YOU.
- GONNA MISS YOU GUYS.
- OH, WELL, WE'LL COME OUT
AND SEE YOU IN--
YEAH,
WE'LL MISS YOU TOO.
- IT'S BEEN NICE
HAVING YOU GUYS AROUND--
YOU KNOW, TO TALK TO.
WELL, SINCE MOM DIED,
IT'S BEEN KIND OF LONELY, AND--
I JUST WISH
WE COULD ALL STAY HERE.
- I--I NEED A HAND
WITH THE VAN, PLEASE.
- OKAY.
- SORRY.
- WELL, I GUESS HE
REALLY MISSES HIS FAMILY.
- WELL, HE DOESN'T KNOW US
VERY WELL.
- YEAH, CLEARLY.
LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
WHERE THE HELL HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHY DIDN'T YOU CALL ME?
- LOOK AT MY LIFE, MICHAEL.
TOBIAS IS OUT OF WORK.
WE'RE IN DEBT.
IT'S...
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
ARE YOU TRYING TO CRY?
- I'M SAD.
LIFE IS HARD RIGHT NOW.
I'VE GOT THE J.D.L. ON MY ASS.
- J.D.L.?
- JEWISH DEFENSE LEAGUE.
- OH, THE CIRCUMCISION THING?
THIS IS WHY I WAS AGAINST HOOP.
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS?
- THIS IS WHY I DIDN'T CALL YOU,
MICHAEL,
BECAUSE YOU'RE SO JUDGMENTAL.
- NO, I'M NOT JUDGMENTAL.
- AND YOU'RE DISAPPOINTED IN ME.
- I'M NOT DISAPPOINTED IN YOU.
- YOU ARE.
- SO I'M DISAPPOINTED IN YOU.
BUT COME ON. WHAT IS NOT
DISAPPOINTING ABOUT MY LIFE?
DAD DIDN'T GIVE ME
THE PROMOTION.
DAD'S IN JAIL.
HOW DISAPPOINTING IS THAT?
- SO WE'RE
A DISAPPOINTING FAMILY.
- WE'RE AN INCREDIBLY
DISAPPOINTING FAMILY.
BUT WE ARE A FAMILY,
AND I WANT MY SON TO BE HAPPY.
SO MAYBE WE SHOULD BE
IN EACH OTHER'S LIVES.
- I'D LIKE THAT.
- YEAH?
SERIOUSLY,
YOU'RE GONNA PULL A MUSCLE.
- I USED TO BE ABLE TO DO THIS.
narrator: SO MICHAEL DECIDED
TO STAY IN CALIFORNIA
AND TRY TO SAVE
THE FAMILY BUSINESS.
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME EVER,
HE GATHERED HIS FAMILY TOGETHER
IN THE MODEL HOME.
- DAD WAS ALWAYS BANKER,
SO THERE WAS NO BEATING HIM.
- TOTALLY.
- HE SHOULD'VE BEEN STOCKING UP
ON THOSE
"GET OUT OF JAIL FREE" CARDS.
- GOOD ONE, GEORGE MICHAEL.
- VERY GOOD.
- THIS IF FUN.
I WISH YOU GUYS
DIDN'T HAVE TO GO SO SOON.
- OH, ON THAT SUBJECT,
THESE GUYS ARE ACTUALLY
GONNA BE STAYING WITH US.
FOR A WHILE., JUST YOUR AUNT
AND HER HUSBAND., NOT GOB.
- REALLY?
- YEAH.
WHAT THE HELL, HUH?
FAMILY FIRST, RIGHT?
IT IS GONNA BE A LITTLE CROWDED,
THOUGH,
SO YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO SHARE
A ROOM WITH YOUR COUSIN.
- [singing] WHAT YOU'RE TRYIN'
TO SAY TO ME
GEORGE MICHAEL
GETS A NEW ROOMMATE.
- [singing]
I'M NOT THAT INNOCENT.
- IT WAS REALLY YOUR BROTHER
WE WERE INTERESTED IN.
I MEAN, YOU DON'T EVEN
HAVE ANY REFERENCES.
- IS THAT ENOUGH
OF A REFERENCE FOR YOU?
narrator: AND MICHAEL
FINDS IT DIFFICULT
TO GET HIS FATHER OUT OF JAIL.
- YOU LOVE IT HERE?
- OH, I'M HAVING
THE TIME OF MY LIFE.
HEY, T-BONE.