narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
- ANOTHER SETBACK FOR THE
ONCE-PROMINENT BLUTH FAMILY
AS THEIR FROZEN BANANA STAND,
A NEWPORT BEACH LANDMARK,
BURNS TO THE GROUND.
A DELICIOUS WHODUNIT AFTER THIS.
[door buzzer buzzing]
narrator:
A WEEK BEFORE THE FIRE,
MICHAEL BLUTH WAS TRYING TO SAVE
THE BLUTH COMPANY,
BUT HIS FATHER
WAS MAKING IT DIFFICULT.
- I NEED THE FLIGHT RECORDS,
DAD.
I'M TRYING TO FIND SOME MONEY
FOR THE FAMILY.
- THERE'S ALWAYS MONEY
IN THE BANANA STAND.
I AM HAVING A LOVE AFFAIR
WITH THIS ICE CREAM SANDWICH.
YOU WANT SOME?
YOU WANNA TAKE A BITE?
- PLEASE, PLEASE.
- COME ON, TAKE A BITE.
- THE S.E.C.
HAS LOCKED UP OUR FUNDS.
THESE GUYS
AREN'T MESSING AROUND.
- NO TOUCHING.
- SO I NEED YOU TO TELL ME,
WERE YOU TAKING VACATIONS
IN THE JET?
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE HIDING
FROM ME?
- [scoffs] I HAVEN'T HAD
A VACATION IN YEARS.
THIS IS MY VACATION.
I'M EXERCISING.
I'M SLEEPING WELL.
- YOU'RE DOING TIME.
- I'M DOING THE TIME OF MY LIFE.
- WHAT'S UP, PUMPKIN?
- HEY, T-BONE.
YEAH,
T-BONE'S MY ROOMMATE.
- OH.
- [whispering] HE'S A FLAMER.
T'S CHECKING OUT TODAY.
- YEAH.
- WELL, I GUESS EVERY VACATION'S
GOTTA COME TO AN END.
- YOU JUST MADE A FOOL OUT OF
YOURSELF IN FRONT OF T-BONE.
ANYWAY, I WANT YOU TO GIVE HIM
A JOB AT THE COMPANY: SALES.
- I'M NOT GONNA DO THAT.
- WHY NOT?
- WELL, BECAUSE...
- BECAUSE HE'S A FLAMER?
- WE DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY.
- BECAUSE I TOLD YOU THAT
IN CONFIDENCE.
- YOU DON'T SEEM TO UNDERSTAND
THAT I'M RUNNING
THIS COMPANY NOW, DAD,
AND I NEED THE FLIGHT RECORDS,
AND I'M GONNA GET THEM
WITH OR WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
- ALL RIGHT.
- NO TOUCHING.
- I GOT SOMETHING WE CAN TRY,
ALL RIGHT?
IT'S A LITTLE RISKY.
- PLEASE.
- OPEN UP.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN, ABOUT...
narrator: WHILE GEORGE SR.
WAS LOSING A ROOMMATE,
GEORGE MICHAEL WAS HAVING A HARD
TIME ADJUSTING TO HIS NEW ONE.
- GET UP. GET UP. GET UP.
GET UP. GET UP.
- I'M UP.
- OKAY, WE ARE JUST ABOUT
ASS TO ANKLES BACK HERE, MAEBY.
DO YOU WANNA HOP ON YOUR
COUSIN'S LAP THERE, PLEASE?
- WHOA, BUMPY ROAD AHEAD.
- [sighs]
[singing]
GOT NOTHIN' ON BUT LOVE NOW.
narrator: SO HE ADDRESSED
HIS PROBLEM HEAD-ON.
- DAD, I WANNA WORK MORE HOURS
AT THE BANANA STAND.
- WOW.
HUH, WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
YOU KNOW, I USED TO BE
JUST LIKE YOU WHEN I WAS A KID.
I USED TO LOVE IT THERE.
- [GEORGE] IT'S GONNA BE OUR
BEST SUMMER EVER, MIKEY.
- WELL, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU A PROMOTION.
WELCOME ABOARD, MR. MANAGER.
- WOW, I'M MR. MANAGER.
- WELL, MANAGER.
WE JUST SAY "MANAGER."
AND YOU CAN HIRE AN EMPLOYEE
IF YOU NEED ONE.
- DO YOU THINK I NEED ONE?
- DON'T LOOK AT ME,
MR. MANAGER.
- RIGHT.
IT'S UP TO ME NOW.
I'M MR. MANAGER.
- MANAGER.
WE JUST SAY...
-I KNOW, BUT YOU JUST--
- IT DOESN'T MATTER WHO.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I EXPECTED.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
THIS IS EXACTLY
WHERE THE TWO OF YOU WERE
WHEN I LEFT THIS MORNING.
- IS NOBODY GONNA EVEN TRY
TO GET A JOB?
- I HAVE A JOB, MICHAEL.
- YEAH?
- IT'S CALLED
SUPPORTING MY HUSBAND.
- WELL, YOU CERTAINLY
HAVEN'T BEEN SHOPPING.
THE ONLY THING I FOUND
IN THE FREEZER
WAS A DEAD DOVE IN A BAG.
- YOU DIDN'T EAT THAT,
DID YOU?
'CAUSE I'VE ONLY GOT A COUPLE
DAYS LEFT TO RETURN IT.
DIED RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF A SHOW.
- DO YOU WANT A CAGE FOR THAT?
- NO.
I'M A MAGICIAN.
[dove cooing]
[bells jingles]
[cooing stops]
WHAT IS YOUR RETURN POLICY,
BY THE WAY?
- NOT THAT I HAVE TO
DEFEND MYSELF,
BUT FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
I DID GO SHOPPING.
- YOU SPENT $68
ON HAIR CONDITIONER?
- A SMALL PRICE TO PAY
FOR SELF-ESTEEM, MICHAEL.
OR ARE YOU STILL JEALOUS
THAT YOU LOST "BEST HAIR" TO ME
IN HIGH SCHOOL AND GOT DORKIEST?
- narrator: LINDSAY'S
ACHIEVEMENTS IN HIGH SCHOOL
HAD ALWAYS OVERSHADOWED
MICHAEL'S.
- I AGREE WITH MICHAEL.
IT'S IMPORTANT NOT TO TIE
YOUR SELF-ESTEEM
INTO HOW YOU LOOK
OR WHAT PEOPLE THINK OF YOU.
I MEAN, LOOK AT ME.
I'M AN ACTOR,
AN ACTOR FOR CRYING OUT LOUD.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW HOW MUCH
REJECTION I FACE EVERY DAY?
BUT IN THIS BUSINESS OF SHOW,
YOU HAVE TO HAVE THE HEART
OF AN ANGEL
AND THE HIDE OF AN ELEPHANT.
- BUT YOU'VE NEVER ACTUALLY HAD
AN AUDITION.
- [chuckles]
WELL...
[imitating Steve Martin]
EXCUSE ME.
- SOME REALLY GREAT
SPOUSAL SUPPORT.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING, LINDSAY?
YOU MIGHT WANNA START THINKING
ABOUT THE EXAMPLE
YOU'RE SETTING
FOR YOUR DAUGHTER,
UNLESS YOU WANT HER TO END UP
JUST LIKE YOU.
- YEAH,
SHOOT ME WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
- IS THERE A CARBON MONOXIDE
LEAK IN THIS HOUSE?
GEORGE MICHAEL, YOU'RE TAKING
YOUR COUSIN TO WORK TODAY.
THAT'S YOUR NEW EMPLOYEE.
I DO NOT WANT MY NIECE TO END UP
JUST LIKE EVERYONE
IN THIS FAMILY.
- UH-UH, YOU'RE NOT TELLING
MY DAUGHTER WHAT TO DO.
SHE'S A CHILD.
- NO, I'M NOT.
I CAN WORK.
- I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THIS.
I MEAN, IT CAN GET PRETTY HAIRY
IN THERE, AND--
- FINE.
DO WHAT YOU WANT.
IF I KNOW MY DAUGHTER, THAT
STAND WON'T BE THERE IN A WEEK.
- YOU STAY ON TOP OF HER, BUDDY.
DO NOT BE AFRAID TO RIDE HER...
HARD.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL'S
ATTEMPT TO DISTANCE HIMSELF
FROM HIS COUSIN
PROVED UNSUCCESSFUL.
- I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW MANY HEALTH CODES
YOU'RE VIOLATING RIGHT NOW.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE I VOLUNTEERED
FOR THIS.
THIS IS MY STUPIDEST
REBELLION EVER.
HEY, DO YOU WANNA GO PLAY
SKEE-BALL?
- [coins jingling]
- WAIT...
THIS IS THE CASH DRAWER.
MY DAD'S GONNA COME BY
AT THE END OF THE WEEKEND,
AND THE NUMBER OF BANANAS
HAS TO MATCH
THE AMOUNT OF MONEY IN HERE.
- OH,
SO IT ALL HAS TO EVEN OUT?
- EXACTLY.
- EASY,
BANANA...BUCK,
BANANA...TAKE A BUCK.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL WENT TO HIS MOTHER
FOR THE FLIGHT RECORDS
HIS FATHER WOULDN'T GIVE HIM.
- THEN WHY DON'T YOU MARRY
AN ICE CREAM SANDWICH?
- I GOTTA GO.
- WHO WAS THAT?
WAS THAT DAD?
- THAT WAS GOB.
- UH-HUH.
SO, MOM, I'M TRYING TO FIND...
- I DON'T KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
- THESE FLIGHT RECORDS.
YOU KNOW, IT'S REALLY MORE
BELIEVABLE IF YOU LET ME FINISH.
WHY AM I THE ONLY ONE
THAT SEEMS TO GET
HOW MUCH TROUBLE
THIS FAMILY IS IN?
- OH, I GET IT, MICHAEL.
I GET IT.
BUT HOW SHOULD I KNOW
WHERE THE RECORDS ARE KEPT?
YOUR FATHER'S IN CHARGE
OF ALL THAT.
- NO, I'M IN CHARGE
OF ALL OF THAT.
AND I THINK THAT YOU DO KNOW
WHERE THEY ARE.
- OH, IT'S PROBABLY ALL
IN A STORAGE UNIT SOMEWHERE.
- WHERE IS THE STORAGE UNIT?
- I DON'T REMEMBER.
- TRY.
- SOMETHING WITH "DALE."
I DON'T KNOW, BROOKFEATHER.
RAINTREE.
IT'S HOT.
IT'S VERY HOT THERE.
I'VE NEVER BEEN.
GET A WARRANT.
- DON'T THINK I WON'T.
MOTHER,  MOTHER,
I CARE ABOUT THIS FAMILY.
- AND I DO TOO, MY DARLING.
THAT'S WHY I'M WORRIED
ABOUT GOB.
I WAS ON THE PHONE WITH HIM
THIS MORNING.
- YOU MEAN, JUST NOW, RIGHT,
WHEN I CAME IN?
- YES, JUST NOW,
WHEN YOU CAME IN.
AND HE'S UPSET.
HE'S VERY UPSET.
- YOU HAVEN'T INCLUDED HIM
IN THE BUSINESS AT ALL.
- HE'S YOUR OLDER BROTHER.
YOU COULD FIND A LITTLE JOB
FOR HIM.
MAKE HIM FEEL SPECIAL.
- BUT HE'S NOT SPECIAL, MOTHER.
- NO.
BUT HE LOVES YOU.
WE ALL LOVE YOU.
- WHERE'S THE STORAGE UNIT?
- IT'S WITH YOUR WARRANT.
- [chuckling]
LUZ, THAT COAT COST MORE
THAN YOUR HOUSE.
OH, THAT'S HOW WE JOKE.
SHE DOESN'T EVEN HAVE A HOUSE.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY,
TOBIAS LOOKED FOR WORK.
- HMM, ACTOR PULL.
OOH.
OH, LOOK AT ALL THESE PARTS.
- TOBIAS,
NICE TO SEE YOU OFF THE COUCH.
- I WAS LOOKING FOR WORK,
AND I BLEW IT, MICHAEL.
- I GUESS YOU'VE ALREADY
SEEN THAT, HUH?
- YES, I HAVE.
OH, RIGHT, THIS ONE.
YEAH, I'LL CALL THEM AGAIN,
I GUESS.
I'LL GIVE THEM ONE MORE SHOT.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN MICHAEL FIGURED OUT
HOW TO GET HIS MOTHER
TO LEAD HIM
TO THE STORAGE UNIT WHERE
THE FLIGHT RECORDS WERE KEPT.
[cell phone rings]
- HELLO.
- HEY, MOM, IT'S MICHAEL.
LISTEN, BEFORE I FORGET,
I TALKED TO THE I.R.S.,
AND THEY WANNA COME BY
YOUR APARTMENT TODAY
TO SEE IF YOU CHARGED ANY
BIG-TICKET STUFF TO THE COMPANY,
FURS OR...I DON'T KNOW.
JUST A HEADS-UP.
OH, THAT POOR WOMAN.
narrator:
SO MICHAEL FOLLOWED LUZ,
WHO HAD BEEN SENT TO HIDE
THE EVIDENCE.
MEANWHILE,
TOBIAS HAD ARRANGED AN AUDITION
FOR A LOCAL COMMERCIAL.
LINDSAY CAME ALONG
TO APPEAR SUPPORTIVE.
- THIS COULD TAKE A WHILE.
- HONEY, IT'S ONE LINE.
- NOT IF I DO MY JOB RIGHT.
FIRST OF ALL, I LOVE IT.
QUICK QUESTION, THOUGH.
AM I PANICKED ABOUT THE FIRE,
OR AM I BEING BRAVE
FOR EVERYONE ELSE?
- THE FIRE...IT'S...
IT'S A FIRE SALE.
- OH.
OKAY, I DIDN'T, UM...
WELL, LET'S GIVE IT A SHOT.
OH, MY GOD.
WE'RE HAVING A FIRE...SALE.
OH, THE BURNING.
IT BURNS ME.
EVACUATE ALL
SCHOOLCHILDREN.
[screaming]
[singing]
AMAAAA...
THIS ISN'T A FEVER.
[singing]
ZING GRACE.
I CAN'T EVEN SEE
WHERE THE KNOB IS.
AND SCENE.
- UM...
WOULD YOU LIKE TO TRY THAT
A LITTLE SIMPLER, MAYBE?
- NO.
- OKAY, ANYBODY ELSE?
ANYONE?
LINDSAY BLUTH?
- IT'S FUNKE.
- ROGER DANISH.
- LOOK AT YOU.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
IT'S LINDSAY BLUTH.
- OH.
- FUNKE.
- ROGER WAS MY MALE COUNTERPART
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
- REMEMBER HOW CRAZY
OUR HAIR WAS BACK THEN?
- WHAT WERE WE THINKING?
SO WHAT ARE YOU DOING NOW?
- HE'S, UH,
CASTING MY COMMERCIAL.
- YEAH, TRYING TO.
THE SOUTH COAST BOUTIQUE
IS HAVING A FIRE SALE.
- SOUTH COAST BOUTIQUE?
THEY'RE HAVING A FIRE SALE?
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL WAS STILL FOLLOWING
HIS MOTHER'S HOUSEKEEPER.
AND SHE DID FINALLY LEAD HIM
TO THE STORAGE UNIT.
UNFORTUNATELY,
IT WAS ON FIRE.
- SOMEBODY WANTED THIS PLACE
TO GO.
- YEAH?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, ARSON?
- OH, DEFINITELY THE WORK
OF A FLAMER.
- [shouting indistinctly]
- IT SHOOTS TOMORROW,
AND ARE YOU READY FOR THIS?
IT PAYS 1,000 BUCKS.
- MM,
I THOUGHT THAT WAS TOBIAS' PART.
- YES
NO, NO, I DID NOT BOOK THIS ONE.
I, UH...
I THINK I MADE THE, UH,
FIRE TOO REAL, UH, FOR THEM,
AND, UH...
AND PROBABLY FAILED
TO HIGHLIGHT THE SALE,
SO GOOD FOR HER, AND, UH,
WILL YOU EXCUSE ME, PLEASE?
[chuckling]
- WELL, THAT'S GREAT,
BUT I'VE GOT MY OWN PROBLEMS.
THE FLIGHT RECORDS,
THEY'VE BURNED UP.
THAT'S FINE.
THAT'S OVER WITH.
BUT I THINK DAD IS BEHIND IT.
I THINK DAD IS TRYING TO RUN
THE BUSINESS FROM PRISON.
- WELL, ISN'T THAT IRONIC?
I'M MAKING A FORTUNE
AT MY NEW JOB,
AND YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE THE JOB
YOU THOUGHT YOU DID.
- BUT YOU DON'T HAVE A JOB.
YOU'VE GOT A JOB OFFER.
ANYBODY CAN GET A JOB OFFER.
- [sobbing]
- SO I'M GONNA GO SEE DAD,
BECAUSE THIS IS MY BUSINESS
TO RUN NOW.
- YOUR BUSINESS?
- HEY, THERE YOU ARE, GOB.
I HAVE BEEN LOOKING ALL OVER
FOR YOU.
I COULD REALLY USE SOME HELP.
- WELL,
I WAS GONNA RETURN THIS DOVE.
WHAT ARE YOU...
YOU WANT ME TO RUN A MEETING
FOR YOU OR SOMETHING?
- OR EVEN BETTER, COULD YOU MAIL
THIS LETTER FOR ME?
- YOU CAN'T JUST GIVE THAT
TO A MAILMAN?
- I CAN'T TRUST A MAILMAN
WITH THIS.
THIS IS IMPORTANT.
narrator:
GOB WAS INTRIGUED.
HE ALSO SUSPECTED
HE COULDN'T RETURN
A COMPLETELY FROZEN DOVE
TO A PET STORE
AND GET THE FULL REFUND HE FELT
HE WAS ENTITLED TO.
- I'LL MAIL THAT LETTER.
narrator: MICHAEL THEN WENT
TO CONFRONT HIS FATHER.
- YOU ARE NOT GOING TO KEEP
RUNNING THE COMPANY
FROM IN HERE, OKAY?
THAT'S WHY YOU WANTED ME
TO GIVE T-BONE A JOB,
TO PAY HIM BACK FOR BURNING DOWN
THE STORAGE UNIT?
- MICHAEL, THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
- WELL, I'M NOT HIRING HIM.
NO.
WE DON'T HAVE THE MONEY, POP.
- THERE'S ALWAYS MONEY
IN THE BANANA STAND.
- THE BANANA STAND.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT THIS FEELS LIKE, HUH,
LIKE I'M STILL STUCK
IN THAT HOT BOOTH ALL SUMMER
WITH YOU PULLING THE STRINGS.
- WHAT WAS I GONNA DO,
PUT A KID
IN CHARGE
OF A FROZEN BANANA STAND?
- SURE.
THAT'S WHAT I DID.
I JUST MADE MY SON THE MANAGER.
- GEORGE MICHAEL IS RUNNING
THE FROZEN BANANA STAND NOW?
- THAT'S RIGHT, YEAH.
YOU SIT WITH THAT.
YOU THINK ABOUT THAT
FOR A WHILE.
narrator: GEORGE SR. DID THINK
ABOUT THAT.
- WELL, NOW THAT WE'VE GOT AN
EMPLOYEE, WE CAN GO HAVE DINNER.
WE THROW AWAY A BANANA
FOR EVERY BUCK WE TAKE
SO NO ONE FINDS OUT.
- WAIT A MINUTE; I THINK YOU
SHOULD DO THAT MATH AGAIN.
- WHY?
IS IT WRONG?
- IT'S FINE.
- HE'S AN ARSONIST,
NOT AN EMBEZZLER.
narrator: MEANWHILE, MICHAEL GOT
AN URGENT CALL FROM HIS MOTHER.
- GOB IS UNHAPPY.
- AGAIN?
I TRIED TO INCLUDE HIM.
I GAVE HIM A JOB.
- YOU GAVE HIM A LETTER TO MAIL.
- DON'T TELL ME THAT WAS
TOO MUCH FOR HIM.
- NO, MICHAEL.
HE MAILED THE LETTER.
THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
narrator:
GOB HAD NOT MAILED THE LETTER,
BUT IN AN ACT OF DEFIANCE
DRAMATICALLY HURLED THE LETTER
INTO THE SEA.
THIS PROVED A MORE DIFFICULT
DRAMATIC GESTURE
THAN HE'D ANTICIPATED.
- [singing breezy,
latin-tinged music]
- SO WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO
ABOUT IT?
- DON'T TAKE THAT TONE.
- HE'S MY SON.
I WANT YOU TO MAKE HIM
STOP CALLING ME.
[door clicks open]
- AM I THE ONLY ONE WHO WORKS
IN THIS FAMILY?
- [chuckling]
YES, THAT'S MY GAL.
WHO WOULD HAVE IMAGINED
TWO ACTORS IN ONE FAMILY?
WE'RE LIKE THE LUNTS.
YOU SEE...EXCUSE ME.
- MAMA.
- muah!
narrator: AND SO LINDSAY
AND MAEBY SEPARATELY WENT
TO THE SAME RESTAURANT
TO CELEBRATE THE JOBS
THEY HADN'T
ACTUALLY PERFORMED
WITH MONEY THEY HADN'T
ACTUALLY EARNED.
- DID YOU ENJOY YOUR MEAL, MOM?'
YOU DRANK IT FAST ENOUGH.
- HI, LUCILLE.
- NOT AS MUCH AS YOU
ENJOYED YOURS.
YOU WANT YOUR BELT TO BUCKLE,
NOT YOUR CHAIR.
- OKAY, THIS IS WHAT I TOLD
TOBIAS YOU'D DO.
SAY WHAT YOU WILL ABOUT HIM.
AT LEAST HE'S HAPPY FOR ME.
- [sobbing]
- YOU KNOW, I THINK WE MIGHT BE
DOUBLING OUR LOSSES HERE.
BECAUSE, I MEAN,
FOR EVERY DOLLAR YOU TAKE,
WE'RE ACTUALLY TAKING
TWO DOLLARS,
BECAUSE WE PAID FOR THE BANANAS.
- [chuckles]
OH, MY GOD, YOU'RE RIGHT.
- I AM?
OH, GOD, I'VE SCREWED THIS UP.
OKAY, WE GOTTA GO.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S YOUR MOM AND GANGY.
- WHAT ARE THEY DOING HERE?
- THEY'RE GROWN-UPS.
THEY'RE ALLOWED TO HAVE FUN
WHENEVER THEY WANT.
WE'RE KIDS.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE WORKING.
NOW THEY'RE GONNA TELL MY DAD,
AND HE'S GONNA COME CHECK
THE TOTALS AND KNOW
WE TOOK THE MONEY.
OH, GOD, THIS IS BAD.
- LOOK...
- WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
- POP-POP,
HE'S A BUSINESS MAN.
WHAT WOULD HE DO?
- BANANAS FOSTER.
- YOU MIGHT WANNA LET
THAT FIRE GO OUT
BEFORE YOU STICK YOUR FACE
IN IT.
- THAT'S FUNNY,
'CAUSE I WAS GONNA SAY,
"YOU MIGHT WANNA LEAN AWAY
FROM THAT FIRE
SINCE YOU'RE SOAKED IN ALCOHOL."
- MINE WAS BETTER.
- WELCOME TO BLUTH BANANAS,
WHERE BANANAS ARE OUR BUSINESS.
MAY I INTEREST YOU IN A BANANA
THIS DAY?
- T-BONE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- OH, YOUR DAD GAVE ME THIS JOB.
narrator: MICHAEL REALIZED
THAT HIS FATHER
HAD EVEN TAKEN CONTROL
OF THE BANANA STAND,
BUT HE STILL HAD
SOME UNANSWERED QUESTIONS,
SO HE DID
A LITTLE DETECTIVE WORK.
- YOU BURN DOWN
THE STORAGE UNIT?
- OH, MOST DEFINITELY.
- MICHAEL, HAVING A NICE DAY
AT THE BEACH,
WHILE THE REST OF US ARE BUSTING
OUR ASSES TO DELIVER YOUR MAIL?
- WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO SAY,
OKAY?
YOU GO AND COMPLAIN TO MOM,
AND I TRIED TO INCLUDE YOU.
- INCLUDE ME?
- YEAH.
- I SHOULD BE IN CHARGE.
I'M THE OLDER BROTHER.
- PLEASE, DO YOU EVEN WANT
TO BE IN CHARGE?
- NO,
BUT I'D LIKE TO BE ASKED.
THIS IS JUST LIKE
WHEN WE WERE KIDS,
AND YOU WERE THE ONLY ONE
HE LET WORK IN THE BANANA STAND.
- WELL, I GOT NEWS FOR YOU, GOB,
DAD STILL DOESN'T TRUST ME
TO THIS DAY.
HE TREATS ME LIKE
A LOW-LEVEL EMPLOYEE.
- BETTER THAN BEING TREATED
LIKE THE GOOFBALL,
THE JOKER,
THE MAGICIAN.
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE GONNA DO,
LIKE, A TRICK THERE,
LIKE THE FIREBALL OR SOMETHING.
- I WAS.
IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
- THESE THINGS NEVER GO OFF
WHEN YOU WANT THEM TO,
MY LEAST-CONSISTENT TRICK.
- HANG ON ONE SEC.
- HELLO.
- HEY, UNCLE MICHAEL,
IT'S ME, MAEBY.
- HEY, MAEBY,
WHERE'S GEORGE MICHAEL?
- AT THE BANANA STAND.
HE'S ABOUT TO DO SOMETHING
REALLY IRRESPONSIBLE.
- YOU THINK IT'S IRRESPONSIBLE?
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
- I'M GONNA GET BLAMED FOR THIS.
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
- DAD.
- HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I WAS JUST, UH...
I WAS BURNING DOWN
THE BANANA STAND.
- WHAT?
- I'M SORRY, DAD.
I SCREWED IT ALL UP.
I'VE GOT NO RIGHT TO CALL MYSELF
MR. MANAGER.
- MANAGER.
- I'M SORRY, DAD.
- OH, GEORGE MICHAEL.
- I AM,
BUT I'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU.
I'LL WORK WEEKNIGHTS.
I'LL LAY PEOPLE OFF.
I'LL GIVE UP MY SUMMER,
ALL MY SUMMERS.
JUST TELL ME WHAT TO DO,
AND I'LL DO IT.
narrator: MICHAEL REALIZED HE
HAD DONE TO HIS SON
WHAT HIS FATHER HAD DONE
TO HIM,
SO HE CAME UP WITH A SOLUTION.
- BURN IT DOWN.
- WHAT?
- LET'S BURN
THIS SON OF A BITCH.
- THIS IS GONNA BE
OUR BEST SUMMER EVER, BUDDY.
narrator: AND SO, MICHAEL,
HIS SON,
AND HIS BROTHER
TOGETHER ENJOYED
THE CATHARTIC BURNING
OF THE BANANA STAND.
YOU MAILED THAT INSURANCE CHECK,
RIGHT, GOB?
- [singing]
AND WE'VE BEEN TAKIN' CARE
OF BUSINESS EVERY DAY
TAKIN' CARE OF BUSINESS
EVERY WAY
WE'VE BEEN TAKIN' CARE
OF BUSINESS
IT'S ALL RIGHT
narrator: THE NEXT MORNING,
LINDSAY WOKE UP LATE IN THE DAY
HUNGOVER FROM CELEBRATING
HER ONE DAY OF EMPLOYMENT,
WHICH, IT TURNS OUT,
SHE HAD SLEPT THROUGH.
- ALL RIGHT, LINDSAY, FORGET IT.
WE'LL GET SOMEONE ELSE.
narrator: TOBIAS WAS NEXT
ON THE CALL LIST,
BUT, UNFORTUNATELY,
COULDN'T HEAR THE PHONE
OVER THE SOUND OF THE SHOWER.
HE DID, HOWEVER,
USE LINDSAY'S CONDITIONER
AND WAS SURPRISED TO FIND THAT
IT DID HELP HIS SELF-ESTEEM.
- MORNIN'.
- YOU LOOK NICE.
- WHAT?
- YOU LOOK VERY HANDSOME TODAY.
- THANK YOU, LINDSAY.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL FINALLY GOT
TO SHOW HIS FATHER WHO'S BOSS.
- YOU WHAT?
- BURNED IT RIGHT DOWN
TO THE GROUND
- ARE YOU CRAZY?
THERE WAS MONEY
IN THAT BANANA STAND.
- WELL, IT'S ALL GONE NOW, DAD,
AND IT WAS MY DECISION.
SO THE NEXT TIME YOU WANNA HAVE
A LITTLE POWER STRUGGLE,
JUST REMEMBER
THAT YOU'RE PLAYING WITH FIRE.
- THERE WAS $250,000 LINING
THE WALLS OF THE BANANA STAND.
- WHAT?
- CASH, MICHAEL.
- WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME THAT?
- HOW MUCH CLEARER CAN I SAY,
"THERE'S ALWAYS MONEY
IN THE BANANA STAND"?
- NO TOUCHING.
- NO TOUCHING..
GOB PROTESTS THE PET STORE'S
FROZEN DOVE EXCHANGE POLICY.
- RETURN FROM WHENCE YOU CAME.
AND, MICHAEL,
REALIZING THE BANANA STAND
IS THE ONLY PROFITABLE PART
OF THE BLUTH EMPIRE,
DECIDES TO REBUILD.
- YOU COULDN'T HAVE CALLED ME?
I CAN'T SWING A HAMMER?
- I GOT A RABBIT TO BUY.