male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
IT WAS SUNDAY MORNING,
AND MICHAEL
WAS MAKING CORNBALLS,
A BLUTH FAMILY FAVORITE
SINCE GEORGE SR. UNSUCCESSFULLY
TRIED TO MARKET THE DEVICE
IN THE MID '70s.
- TIME TO PULL OUT THE BASKET,
AND WE DIG INTO SOME HOT--
SON OF A BITCH!
- OH!
LOOK WHAT YOU DID!
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU,
YOU MINCING--
[all gasp]
narrator: IT WAS A RITUAL
MICHAEL SHARED WITH HIS SON
BEFORE THEIR WEEKLY BIKE RIDE
TO BALBOA ISLAND.
- CAREFUL!
DON'T TOUCH THAT.
NEVER TOUCH THAT.
REALLY LOOKING FORWARD
TO OUR RIDE TODAY.
WE BETTER GO EXTRA HARD TO
WORK OFF THESE CORNBALLS, HUH?
- OR YOU COULD NOT
EAT THE CORNBALLS
AND LET YOUR KID
LEAD HIS OWN LIFE.
- PLEASE--HE LOVES THIS.
AM I RIGHT?
- ACTUALLY...
I CAN'T REALLY GO TODAY.
- HOW'S THAT?
- MY--MY BIKE NEEDS A TUNE-UP
OR SOMETHING.
- LET'S NOT BLAME THE BIKE,
OKAY?
IT'S THE POOR CARPENTER
THAT BLAMES HIS SHODDY TOOLS--
OW!
[bleep]!
OH, THAT STUPID CORNBALLING
PIECE OF [bleep].
MM.
- SO I'M GONNA GO, OKAY?
- YEAH, YEAH, IT'S FINE.
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S OKAY, HAVE FUN.
- GETTING TOO OLD FOR HIS DADDY?
- NO, HE'LL BE FINE.
AND I WOULD BUY HIM
A FASTER BIKE
IF WE WEREN'T TRYING
TO SAVE EVERY--
DID YOU GO SHOPPING?
- OH, YEAH,
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I PAID FOR IT MYSELF.
- WITH WHAT?
- COMPANY CREDIT CARD.
- YOU'RE RETURNING THAT.
- BUT--
- GET A JOB.
- MICHAEL.
HEY, THE CORNBALLER!
I THOUGHT THESE THINGS
WERE ONLY LEGAL IN MEXICO.
narrator:
IN FACT, THE CORNBALLER
WASN'T LEGAL ANYWHERE,
BUT GEORGE SR. CONTINUED
TO MARKET IT THERE SUCCESSFULLY.
- MUY DELICIOSO.
- [speaking Spanish]
- iSOY LOCO POR LOS CORNBALLS!
- WHERE'D YOU COME FROM?
- I HAD ANOTHER BIG FIGHT
WITH MARTA.
narrator:
GOB HAD BEEN HAVING
AN ON-AGAIN, OFF-AGAIN
RELATIONSHIP WITH MARTA,
A SPANISH-LANGUAGE
SOAP OPERA STAR.
- IT LOOKS LIKE I'M GONNA BE
STAYING HERE FOR A WHILE.
- NO, IT DOESN'T.
IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE THAT.
I'VE GOT A FULL HOUSE HERE, GOB.
- HE'S JUST IN A BAD MOOD, GOB,
BECAUSE HIS SON
FEELS SUFFOCATED BY HIM.
- SUFFOCATED?
REALLY?
- YES, MICHAEL,
HE'S A TEENAGER.
HE'S PROBABLY GOT
A LITTLE GIRLFRIEND, AND...
WELL, LET'S FACE IT.
YOU ARE OVERBEARING.
- MAYBE I SHOULD BE
A LITTLE BIT MORE LIKE YOU
WHEN IT COMES TO PARENTING, HUH?
NO BORDERS, NO LIMITS,
"GO AHEAD, TOUCH THE CORNBALLER.
YOU KNOW BEST."
- MICHAEL, IF I COULD
STICK MY PRETTY LITTLE NOSE
IN HERE FOR ONE SECOND...
WHEN I WAS A PSYCHIATRIST,
AND THIS IS BEFORE
I BECAME AN ACTOR--
- YOU'RE STILL NOT AN ACTOR.
- LOVELY.
I SAW A LOT OF THIS TYPE
OF BEHAVIOR,
AND I THINK
WHAT YOU'RE EXPERIENCING
IS YOUR SON'S VERY NORMAL NEED
TO DISTANCE HIMSELF
FROM HIS OVERBEARING FATHER.
AM I TOUCHING SOMETHING?
HOT.
HOT-HOT.
- BE CAREFUL.
- [gasping]
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
- AH, YES...
NOW, TAKE MY DAUGHTER,
FOR EXAMPLE.
SHE LIVES HER LIFE,
AND I GET THE PLEASURE
OF GUESSING
WHAT THAT MIGHT ENTAIL.
NOW, WATCH THIS.
MAEBY, WHERE ARE YOU OFF TO
ON THIS GLORIOUS
SUNDAY AFTERNOON?
[sotto voce]
SHE WON'T TELL ME.
- I'M GOING TO AUDITION
FOR A PLAY.
- WELL, THAT TIME
IT DIDN'T WORK.
WHAT--WHAT PLAY?
- IT'S FOR HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU CAN'T AUDITION.
- I WAS TOTALLY WRONG.
SHE'S REACHING OUT
TO HER ACTOR DADDY.
DOES ANYONE HAVE AN ICE PACK?
narrator: IN TRUTH, MAEBY WAS
REACHING OUT TO A BOY
NAMED STEVE HOLT,
WHO WAS AUDITIONING FOR THE LEAD
IN A SCHOOL PLAY.
- "I WOULD KISS
BEFORE I SPOKE."
narrator: MAEBY DECIDED
TO AUDITION AS WELL,
LOOKING FOR A CHANCE
TO GET CLOSER TO STEVE.
- AND THEN WE ACTUALLY
GET TO KISS, RIGHT?
- GEORGE MICHAEL ALSO CHOSE
TO AUDITION,
LOOKING FOR A CHANCE TO GET
CLOSER TO HIS COUSIN MAEBY.
- "I WOULD KISS
BEFORE I SPOKE."
AND THEN THERE'S A KISS, RIGHT?
- LOUDER.
- AND THEN THERE'S A KISS,
RIGHT?
narrator: LATER, THE CAST LIST
WAS POSTED.
- STEVE HOLT!
- STAND-IN FOR STEVE HOLT?
narrator: MICHAEL WENT
TO GET HIS SON A NEW BIKE
TO KEEP HIM FROM SLIPPING AWAY,
WHILE MICHAEL'S MOTHER
WAS GIVING UP HOPE
THAT HER SON BUSTER
WOULD EVER LEAVE HER SIDE.
- ZIP ME UP.
narrator:
USUALLY AT THIS TIME OF YEAR,
BUSTER WOULD RETURN TO
HIS POST-GRADUATE STUDIES.
BUT WITHOUT THE RESOURCES
TO AFFORD IT,
HIS SUMMER VACATION
WAS EXTENDING INTO THE FALL.
- MOM! MOM!
WHOO-HOO!
narrator: AND LUCILLE WAS
BEGINNING TO RESENT IT.
[ringing]
- WHAT?
- HI, MAMA, IT'S LINDS.
- IT'LL FLY OUT ON ITS OWN.
WHY ARE YOU CALLING ME?
WHAT DO YOU NEED?
- VERY NICE, MOM.
I DON'T NEED ANYTHING.
MY DAUGHTER NEEDS
SOME NEW SCHOOL CLOTHES.
- BUSTER!
- IT'S A BIRD.
- I KNOW IT'S A BIRD.
I'M ON THE PHONE.
- IT WALKED ON MY PILLOW!
- LOOK, I HAVE A CHILD THAT
COSTS ME MONEY TOO, YOU KNOW.
WHY CAN'T YOU GET A JOB?
- WHAT IS IT WITH
THIS FAMILY AND WORKING?
MICHAEL JUST GAVE ME
THE EXACT SAME LECTURE
IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY.
- EVERYBODY?
WHO'S EVERYBODY?
[glass breaking]
- YOU KNOW, THE KIDS,
GOB, TOBIAS, EVERYBODY.
[wings flapping]
- HE DIDN'T INVITE BUSTER.
BUSTER'S HIS BROTHER TOO.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH BUSTER?
narrator: AND EVEN AS SHE ASKED
THE QUESTION, LUCILLE REALIZED
THAT PERHAPS IT WAS TIME
TO LET HER OWN BABY BIRD
FLY AWAY.
- WHY DO I HAVE TO TAKE HIM?
- BECAUSE HE'S YOUR BROTHER.
AND YOU RUN AROUND
WITH EVERYONE ELSE,
GOING ON BIKE RIDES,
MAKING CORNHOLES.
- MOM, LISTEN--
- EVERYONE'S LAUGHING AND RIDING
AND CORNHOLING EXCEPT BUSTER.
AND I KNOW HE'S NOT THE
SHARPEST KNIFE IN THE DRAWER,
BUT HE'S SENSITIVE, MICHAEL,
AND YOU COULD PRETEND
TO BE INTERESTED IN HIM.
- FINE, HE CAN HANG OUT,
BUT HE'S GOING TO WORK, OKAY?
THIS IS NOT GOING TO BE
A DAY AT THE BEACH.
- TH-THAT'S COOL.
MOM PACKED ME
A CHANGE OF CLOTHES.
narrator:
SO BUSTER STAYED,
AND MICHAEL MADE HIM
BUILD THE NEW BIKE.
- IT'S IN THAT BIG BOX
IN MY OFFICE.
HEY.
- MICHAEL.
- GOB, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE,
AND WHY ARE YOU IN A BATHROBE?
- WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
WHY IS HE IN HIS BATHING SUIT?
- MOM DROPPED ME OFF
TO SPEND TIME WITH MICHAEL.
- SPEND TIME WITH MICHAEL,
OR TO SERVE HER OWN
MENOPAUSAL NEEDS?
- SHE'S ALWAYS GOT TO WEDGE
HERSELF IN THE MIDDLE OF US
SO SHE CAN CONTROL EVERYTHING.
- YEAH.
MOM'S AWESOME.
MAYBE WE SHOULD CALL HER.
- SO WHY ARE YOU IN YOUR ROBE?
- I CAMPED OUT IN
THE BOARDROOM LAST NIGHT.
WHAT WITH YOU KICKING ME
OUT OF YOUR HOUSE--[sniffs]
THERE ARE FEW PLACES LEFT
THAT YOU HAVE THAT I CAN STAY.
- HMM, WELL,
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE EITHER.
- [scoffs]
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
IS THIS A BUSINESS DECISION,
OR IS IT PERSONAL?
'CAUSE IF IT'S BUSINESS,
I'LL GO AWAY HAPPILY.
BUT IF IT'S PERSONAL,
I'LL GO AWAY,
BUT I WON'T BE HAPPY.
- IT'S PERSONAL.
- I AM SO SORRY.
narrator:
MICHAEL'S SON, MEANWHILE,
WAS WAITING WITH HIS COUSIN
FOR THEIR FIRST REHEARSAL.
- I'M SURPRISED
YOU TRIED OUT FOR THIS.
- YEAH, I JUST LOVE THE THEATER.
- THAT'S GREAT.
I'M JUST DOING IT
TO KISS STEVE HOLT.
- WELL, ACTUALLY,
I THINK I'M GONNA QUIT.
YEAH, THEATER'S DEAD.
- BUT HE'S ALWAYS GOING
TO BE AT FOOTBALL PRACTICE,
SO I'M GONNA HAVE TO KISS
THE STAND-IN.
- BUT, NO, NO,
I LOVE THE THEATER,
AND I GAVE MY WORD,
SO I'M BACK IN.
narrator: TOBIAS, MEANWHILE,
STOPPED BY THE SCHOOL.
- I KNOW WHY YOU'RE DOING THIS.
- DAD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
GO AWAY.
- YES, BECAUSE THE DIRECTOR
MIGHT BE HERE SOON, RIGHT?
OOPS.
TOO LATE.
HE'S ALREADY HERE.
HELLO, EVERYONE,
AND WELCOME TO THE THEATER.
I AM DR. TOBIAS FUNKE,
AND I WILL BE
YOUR NEW DIRECTOR.
- OH, MY GOD.
- [chuckles]
narrator: TOBIAS HAD GOTTEN
THE DIRECTING JOB
BY MEETING
WITH THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL.
- AND YOU TELL ME YOU'VE GOT
SOME P.E. TEACHER DIRECTING?
THAT JUST MAKES ME WANT TO
PUKE ALL OVER YOUR HEAD, SIR.
GIVE ME A CHANCE
TO TELL THE BARD'S TALE,
AND I GIVE YOU MY WORD
ON HUMBLE KNEE,
WHENCE YOU SHALL NOT SAY
IT WASN'T E'ER TO BE.
- JERRY, YOU COOL WITH THIS?
- SURE.
LET THE LITTLE FRUIT DO IT.
- HUZZAH!
narrator:
AS THE DAYS WENT BY,
BUSTER'S APPRENTICESHIP
WAS PROVING
MORE TRYING
THAN MICHAEL HAD ANTICIPATED.
- WE'RE EXCITED.
WE WANT YOUR BUSINESS.
- [yawns loudly]
- AND, UH, EVERYBODY
AT THE BLUTH COMPANY--
- [yawns loudly]
HERE I GO AGAIN.
narrator: AND JUST WHEN
HE COULD TAKE NO MORE...
- AND WE'RE BACK ON TRACK.
AND WE'RE FOCUSED.
[clattering]
AND, BUSTER,
YOU CAN'T DO THAT
IN THE SNACK ROOM, PAL?
- MOM TOLD ME TO
STAY AWAY FROM MICROWAVES.
AND BESIDES, THIS IS GONNA BE
THE MOST BITCHINGLY FAST BIKE
IN ALL OF ORANGE COUNTY.
- REALLY?
- YOUR SON IS GONNA LOVE IT.
- WELL, I GUESS 3:40
IS AS GOOD A TIME AS ANY
TO CALL IT A DAY.
narrator: SO MICHAEL LEFT
FOR THE HIGH SCHOOL
HOPING TO RECONNECT
WITH HIS SON,
WHILE TOBIAS'S ATTEMPT
TO RECONNECT WITH HIS DAUGHTER
HIT A SNAG.
- STOP! STOP IT. IT'S ALL WRONG.
- BUT WE WERE JUST ABOUT
TO DO THE KISS--
- KISS.
I KNOW.
IT DOESN'T WORK.
LOOK, YOU ARE PLAYING ADULTS
WITH FULLY--
PICK THAT UP, PLEASE--
WITH FULLY FORMED LIBIDOS,
NOT TWO YOUNG MEN
PLAYING GRAB-ASS IN THE SHOWER.
[clattering]
WOULD YOU HOLD THE WORK, PLEASE?
OH, MICHAEL.
- DAD, WH--
- SO, YOU'RE IN A PLAY, HUH?
- I'M NOT.
I QUIT.
- MAEBY.
- WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME?
- WELL, IT'S NOT
REALLY IMPORTANT.
I'M JUST A STAND-IN.
- AND YOU'RE ASHAMED.
WELL, THIS SHOULD
CHEER YOU UP, HMM?
I LEFT WORK EARLY.
I THOUGHT MAYBE WE'D GO
FOR A RIDE TODAY.
- NO, I CAN'T GO
ON A BIKE RIDE RIGHT NOW.
- WHY, BECAUSE OF THE PLAY?
YOU'RE JUST A STAND-IN.
- NO, NO, IT'S NOT THE PLAY.
IT'S JUST--
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T GO ON
A MILLION BIKE RIDES
WHENEVER YOU WANT ME TO.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
HEY, IS IT ABOUT A GIRL?
- NO! IT'S NOT.
JUST DROP IT, DAD.
- WHAT, IS LINDSAY RIGHT?
AM I REALLY SUFFOCATING HIM?
- WELL, THEY'RE DIFFERENT PEOPLE
EVERY DAY, TEENAGERS.
HORMONES ALL ABLAZE.
EXCEPT, OF COURSE,
WHEN THEY'RE ON STAGE,
WHEN I NEED IT.
- NO, HE SAID IT WASN'T
ABOUT A GIRL.
[sighs]
MAYBE HE REALLY IS PULLING AWAY.
- NOT A GIRL?
OF COURSE.
METHINKS A CUPID
I SHALL PLAY.
MM. MMM. MMM.
narrator: TOBIAS CAME UP WITH
A NEW PLAN FOR THE PLAY...
AND A WAY TO CONNECT
TO GEORGE MICHAEL.
- I KNOW WHY YOU'RE IN THE PLAY.
- WHAT?
- WATCH THIS.
OKAY, EVERYBODY.
WELL, WE'VE LOST A LEADING LADY,
BUT DID YOU KNOW
THAT IN SHAKESPEARE'S DAY
THAT THE WOMEN'S ROLES...
WERE PLAYED BY MEN?
FANCY THAT.
HMM.
GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU KNOW STEVEN'S LINES, YES?
- SORT OF.
- FINE.
THEN YOU ARE MY BENEDICT.
AND STEVEN HOLT--
WHERE IS STEVEN HOLT?
- STEVE HOLT!
- YES, GET READY
FOR THE ACTING CHALLENGE
OF YOUR SWEET YOUNG LIFE,
FAIR LADY,
FOR YOU ARE MY BEATRICE.
- BEATRICE!
LET'S TAKE IT FROM, "PEACE,
I WILL STOP THY MOUTH."
AND NOW WE'LL SEE
IF SOME SPARKS FLY.
narrator:
AS GEORGE MICHAEL CONTEMPLATED
KISSING HIS RIVAL,
MICHAEL SOUGHT
HIS FATHER'S ADVICE.
- YOU THINK YOU NEVER HURT ME?
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHEN HAVE I EVER REBELLED?
- I NEVER SEE YOU ANYMORE,
MICHAEL.
- YOU'RE IN PRISON.
AND I WAS HERE YESTERDAY.
- OH, YEAH, THAT'S-THAT'S--
I'M SORRY.
I COULDN'T BREAK AWAY
FROM THE POKER GAME.
CAPITAL "G"
WAS DOWN TO HIS BOXERS.
- STRIP POKER?
- YEAH, AND IT'S TOUGH.
WE CAN REALLY
ONLY PLAY ABOUT TWO HANDS.
LISTEN--
[exhales]
LET HIM GO.
LET YOUR SON GO.
- I CAN'T DO THAT, DAD.
HE NEEDS ME.
- MICHAEL, YOU DON'T WANT TO
MAKE THE SAME MISTAKE
YOUR MOM MADE WITH BUSTER.
- YEAH, BOY.
WHAT HAPPENED THERE?
- I REALLY DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE IT WAS THE 11 MONTHS
HE SPENT IN THE WOMB.
THE DOCTOR SAID
THERE WERE CLAW MARKS
ON THE WALLS
OF HER UTERUS, BUT...
HE WAS OUR MIRACLE BABY,
YOU KNOW?
AND I WAS JUST TOO BURNED OUT
ON RAISING YOU GUYS TO CARE,
SO...HE TURNED OUT
A LITTLE, UH, SOFT.
- [yawns loudly]
- A LITTLE DOUGHY.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE IT WAS MY FAULT.
- [continues yawning]
- MAYBE I JUST IGNORED THE GUY.
- WOW, WE'RE JUST BLOWING
THROUGH NAP TIME, AREN'T WE?
- YEAH, I GOTTA LET MY SON GO.
narrator: LINDSAY, MEANWHILE,
STILL HAD THE DRESS,
AND SHE WAS STARTING TO GET
SOME POSITIVE REACTIONS TO IT.
- LOOK AT YOU.
- I AM.
narrator: SO SHE DECIDED
TO HIDE IT
IN THE ATTIC CRAWL SPACE.
- [snoring]
[loud piano]
- [singing]
YOU'RE AS COLD AS ICE
WILLING TO SACRIFICE
[piano lid slams]
ARE YOU CRAZY?
I'M A MAGICIAN.
I MAKE MY LIVING WITH MY HANDS.
AND IF I'M GOING TO BE
STAYING HERE--
- STAYING HERE?
WHAT, DID THAT MEXICAN
THROW YOU OUT?
- SHE'S NOT
"THAT MEXICAN," MOM.
SHE'S MY MEXICAN.
AND SHE'S COLOMBIAN
OR SOMETHING.
ANYWAY, IT'S OVER.
- YOU'VE GOT THREE DAYS.
- HEY, IF I CAN'T FIND
A HORNY IMMIGRANT BY THEN,
I DON'T DESERVE TO STAY HERE.
[both laugh]
OH!
narrator:
BACK AT THE MODEL HOME,
MICHAEL WAS ADJUSTING
TO THE ABSENCE OF HIS SON
BY ENJOYING THE COMPANY
OF HIS BROTHER.
- YOU KNOW,
I'M IN PRETTY GOOD SHAPE.
YOU COULD BE EATING MY DUST
ALL DAY, SLOWPOKE.
narrator:
AND BUSTER WAS STARTING
TO GIVE AS GOOD AS HE GOT.
- YEAH, AND YOU MIGHT BE
EATING [bleep]...
[bleeping continues]
- WELL, LET'S HOPE
IT DOESN'T COME TO THAT.
[footsteps approaching]
HEY, TOBIAS.
HOW'S MY SON DOING?
- OH, WELL, HE DIDN'T WANT
TO REHEARSE TODAY,
BUT I DO THINK I HAVE A HANDLE
ON WHAT HE'S GOING THROUGH.
I WISH I COULD SAY THE SAME
FOR STEVE HOLT, THOUGH.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE HELL
HER PROBLEM IS.
- HER?
- OH, UH, I'M SORRY.
I SAY THAT BECAUSE
I SWITCHED THE PARTS,
BUT IT'S STILL--[sighs]
OFF.
PERHAPS IF
SHE DRESSED AS A WOMAN.
- SHE?
- OH, FOR THE LOVE OF GOD.
SHE'S PLAYING A WOMAN.
- LOOK WHO'S BACK.
- I'M EXHAUSTED.
- NEIMAN'S AGAIN, HUH?
- ACTUALLY, I'VE BEEN GOING
TO THE THRIFT STORE,
BUT I'M GOING TO FIND
A WAY TO KEEP THAT DRESS.
- THINGS DIDN'T WORK OUT
WITH MOM.
IT WAS UTTERLY MACABRE.
- ZIP ME UP.
- SHE ALWAYS MAKES EVERYTHING
ABOUT HER.
- [groans]
SHE'S THE LAST PERSON
I EVER WANT TO
NEED SOMETHING FROM.
- WELL, SHE LIKES TO BE NEEDED,
JUST AS LONG AS IT DOESN'T
COST HER ANYTHING.
- IT'S LIKE SHE GETS OFF
ON BEING WITHHOLDING.
- WHOA, BUSTER.
- LOOK WHO'S GOT
SOMETHING TO SAY.
- [giggles]
I'M MOM, AND I WANNA
SHOOT DOWN EVERYTHING YOU SAY
SO I FEEL GOOD ABOUT MYSELF.
[blows, giggles]
- LOOK WHO'S RAGGING
ON THE OLD LADY.
- HEY, HEY.
- FINALLY.
- 'CAUSE I'M AN UPTIGHT
[long bleep]
BUSTER!
YOU OLD HORNY SLUT!
- WELL, NO ONE'S GONNA TOP THAT.
narrator: AND TOBIAS HAD FOUND
THE PERFECT WARDROBE
FOR HIS LEADING MAN,
THE RED DRESS HE DISCOVERED
IN THE ATTIC CRAWL SPACE.
ASSUMING MICHAEL HAD
FOUND AND RETURNED IT,
LINDSAY CALLED HER MOTHER,
HOPING TO GET MONEY
FOR A NEW ONE.
- WHAT?
- HI, MAMA. IT'S LINDS.
- GET A JOB.
- LOOK, JUST HEAR ME OUT.
IT'S MAEBY'S DRESS.
IT WAS STOLEN FROM HER LOCKER.
THEY BEAT HER UP
AND, UH, TOOK ALL HER CLOTHES.
- SEND HER OVER.
I'LL TAKE HER SHOPPING.
- BUSTER WAS RIGHT.
YOU GET OFF ON BEING
WITHHOLDING, DON'T YOU?
- BUSTER SAID THAT?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- MY BUSTER?
- NOT ANYMORE, APPARENTLY.
narrator: WHILE LUCILLE
WAS MISSING HER YOUNGEST SON,
MICHAEL WAS FINALLY
ENJOYING HIS COMPANY.
- ZIP ME UP.
narrator: AND WHILE BUSTER
DID BUILD A FASTER BIKE...
HE NEGLECTED
TO BUILD THE BRAKES.
- I'M FLYING!
[loud crash]
- BUSTER?
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
HAD NEWS FOR MAEBY.
- SO I QUIT THE PLAY.
I DON'T REALLY LIKE PLAYS.
ALSO, I THINK YOUR DAD
THINKS I'M GAY.
- OH, HE THINKS EVERYONE'S GAY.
- SO DO YOU WANNA GET A SODA?
- I CAN'T.
I'M ACTUALLY BACK IN THE PLAY.
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF DRESS REHEARSAL RIGHT NOW.
- BUT I THOUGHT
STEVE HAD YOUR PART.
narrator: STEVE DID STILL
HAVE MAEBY'S PART.
AND TOBIAS HAD GIVEN MAEBY
A NEW PART.
- SO YOU WANT ME
TO PLAY THE MAN?
- YES. DON'T YOU SEE?
I CAST THE PARTS ALL WRONG.
IT WAS DADDY'S FAULT.
- AND I STILL GET TO
KISS STEVE, RIGHT?
IT'S GONNA BE
A HUGE DISASTER.
I'LL GET YOU TICKETS.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL TRIED TO SALVAGE
WHAT WAS LEFT OF THE DAY...
WITH WHAT WAS LEFT
OF HIS BROTHER.
I'M A LITTLE SHAKY, BUT--
- BUT WE'RE HERE TO WORK.
- MICHAEL.
- MOM.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- OH, HELLO, BUSTER.
HERE'S A CANDY BAR.
- OH--
- NO, I'M WITHHOLDING IT.
LOOK AT ME GETTING OFF.
HOW DARE YOU
TURN BUSTER AGAINST ME.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- I KNOW WHAT
YOU'VE ALL BEEN SAYING.
BUT I'M NOT GOING TO LET YOU
DESTROY MY RELATIONSHIP
WITH MY SON
JUST BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE ONE
WITH YOURS RIGHT NOW.
- WAIT A MINUTE,
ME AND MY SON ARE FINE,
AND THAT IS NOT WHAT THIS IS.
BUSTER IS A GROWN MAN.
HE CAN MAKE HIS OWN DECISIONS.
WHY DON'T YOU ASK BUSTER
WHAT HE WANTS.
- MICHAEL,
I WANT TO GO WITH MOM.
- YOU SAID THAT
SHE SHOOTS YOU DOWN.
- I WAS JUST TRYING TO FIT IN.
- YOU WERE FLYING TODAY, BUDDY.
- YES, I WAS FLYING,
BUT A LITTLE TOO CLOSE
TO THE SUN.
- YOU LET HIM GO IN THE SUN?
GET IN THE BACK SEAT.
I'LL BE RIGHT OUT.
- FRONT SEAT, MOM.
I SIT IN THE FRONT SEAT NOW.
HMM?
- LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
MICHAEL.
YOU HAVE TO FIGHT
FOR YOUR FAMILY.
IF YOU WERE SMART,
YOU'D GRAB YOUR SON
BEFORE HE SLIPS
ANY FURTHER AWAY.
- WELL, I DISAGREE, MOM.
I'M NOT GONNA CONTROL
GEORGE MICHAEL.
I'M GONNA LET HIM
DECIDE FOR HIMSELF WHAT'S BEST.
- MM-HMM, WELL,
YOU BETTER HOPE
THAT LITTLE BIRD DECIDES
TO FLY BACK INTO YOUR HOUSE,
BECAUSE THEY USUALLY DON'T.
- SO, UH...
CAN WE GO NOW?
- YEAH.
narrator:
AND GEORGE MICHAEL WATCHED
AS MAEBY SHARED THE KISS
THAT SHOULD'VE BEEN HIS
WITH THE BOY
HE ALMOST HAD TO KISS.
BUT, TO MAEBY'S SURPRISE,
SHE DID NOT ENJOY
KISSING STEVE HOLT.
- YOU SMELL LIKE MY MOM.
narrator: AND MICHAEL RETURNED
TO THE MODEL HOME
TO FIND HIS SON IN THE KITCHEN.
- YOU'RE HOME.
- YEAH, I WAS WAITING FOR YOU.
I THOUGHT WE COULD
MAKE SOME OF THESE.
- SURE.
- I'M SORRY ABOUT
WHAT I SAID AT THE SCHOOL.
IT WAS OUT OF LINE.
- I SHOULDN'T HAVE POKED
MY NOSE INTO YOUR LIFE.
- MY LIFE?
- I KNOW THAT YOU'RE GROWING UP.
- YEAH, BUT DAD,
YOU'RE, LIKE,
THE MOST IMPORTANT PART
OF MY LIFE.
- THAT'S A LITTLE CORNBALL.
- I DON'T MIND.
- I DON'T MIND EITHER, BUDDY.
- WATCH YOUR--
- MOTHER OF GOD!
OH!
EVERY DAMN TIME!
THIS IS A BIG ONE--OH!
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT"...
TOBIAS GETS A REVIEW
OF HIS SHAKESPEARE PLAY.
- I DIDN'T GET
INTO THIS BUSINESS
TO PLEASE SOPHOMORE
TRACY SCHWARTZMAN, SO...
ONWARD AND UPWARD!
ON--
WHY, TRACY?
WHY?
narrator: AND BUSTER IS BACK
WHERE HE BELONGS.
- MOM!
- WHAT IS IT?
- I CAN'T GET DOWN.