- MICHAEL BLUTH ARRIVED HOME
TO FIND THE RENTAL CAR
HIS SISTER, LINDSAY,
HAD PROMISED TO RETURN.
- LINDSAY, YOU HAVE TO CUT BACK
ON EVERYTHING.
OKAY? I'M EVEN
SELLING THE CORPORATE JET.
- GREAT. SO NOW WE DON'T HAVE
A CAR OR A JET?
WHY DON'T WE JUST TAKE AN AD OUT
IN "I'M POOR" MAGAZINE?
- LOOK, I'M TRYING TO GET
DEVELOPMENT STARTED, ALL RIGHT?
I'VE GOT SIX GUYS ON BULLDOZERS
WAITING TO GET UNDERWAY.
- BULLDOZING?
- YEAH.
- WELL, WHAT ABOUT THE TREES?
- OH, WE'RE JUST GONNA
COVER THEM WITH BLANKETS.
I'M RIPPING 'EM OUT.
- ANYTHING FOR A BUCK, RIGHT?
YOU ARE SO MATERIALISTIC.
- DON'T SUDDENLY TURN THIS
INTO ONE OF YOUR CAUSES.
- IT'S NOT SUDDEN, MICHAEL.
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN DEEPLY
PASSIONATE ABOUT NATURE.
PERHAPS YOU REMEMBER NEUTERFEST?
- I'LL NEVER FORGET
YOUR WEDDING.
- I CARE DEEPLY FOR NATURE.
- YOU'RE WEARING
OSTRICH SKIN BOOTS.
- WELL, I DON'T CARE
ABOUT OSTRICHES.
- YOU'RE LOOKING AT
A DESPERATE MAN, MICHAEL.
- DO YOU NEED MONEY?
- WHAT I NEED IS FREEDOM.
MARTA IS BEING
INTERVIEWED TODAY ON TV
ABOUT HER SHOW,
"EL AMOR PROHIBIDO."
I MEAN, IT'S BAD ENOUGH THAT I
GOTTA GO TO THE AWARDS SHOW
TOMORROW NIGHT.
TODAY I GOTTA STAND NEXT TO HER
LIKE I'M RITA WILSON.
- GOB'S GIRLFRIEND MARTA HAD BEN
NOMINATED FOR A DAYTIME DESI,
THE AWARD GIVEN FOR EXCELLENCE
IN SPANISH DAYTIME TELEVISION.
- GOB, YOU FOUND A WOMAN
WHO BELIEVES IN YOU.
YOU SHOULD MAKE A COMMITMENT TO
HER, 'CAUSE LIFE IS SHORT.
LISTEN TO ME.
I WOULD GIVE ANYTHING
TO BE ABLE TO HAVE THAT AGAIN.
YOU KNOW? A FAMILY?
NOTHING ELSE MATTERS.
- MICHAEL!
- THAT'S MOM. HIDE.
- [whispering]
YOU BROUGHT UP MONEY EARLIER.
I ACTUALLY WOULD LIKE
TO BORROW SOME.
- NO.
- MICHAEL?
- HE'S IN HERE, MOM!
- COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
NO WAY. THAT'S MINE.
GIVE IT TO ME!
- GOB, WAIT!
I NEED THOSE TICKETS!
- [sighs]
- HE PROMISED ME TICKETS
TO HIS GIRLFRIEND'S AWARDS SHOW.
- YOU'RE GOING
TO THAT THING?
- WELL, MY DEAR FRIEND
LUCILLE AUSTERO
IS PART OWNER
OF A TELEVISION STATION,
AND I WANT TO SHOW UP
AND HOLD MY HEAD HIGH.
I MAY NOT HAVE HER MONEY
ANYMORE,
BUT AT LEAST
I HAVE A LIVE HUSBAND.
- AH, SHE'S LUCKY TO HAVE YOU
AS A FRIEND.
BUSTER.
- HEY, BROTHER.
UH, MOM SAID YOU COULD
TIE THIS FOR ME.
- MAKE IT LONG SO BUSTER DOESN'T
SEEM SO...ROUND.
- COME HERE, PAL.
- THANK YOU.
- WHAT, DO YOU GUYS
GOT A BIG DATE?
- WELL, WE'RE NOT DATING.
[chuckles]
- NONETHELESS--
COME HERE--
SHOULDN'T BUSTER
BE SPENDING HIS EVENINGS
WITH WOMEN THAT AREN'T SO
MUCH...HIS MOTHER?
- HE'S A BEAUTIFUL BOY.
THEY DON'T APPRECIATE HIM.
IT'S HIS GLASSES.
THEY MAKE HIM LOOK
LIKE A LIZARD.
- PLUS, HE'S SELF-CONSCIOUS.
- GEE, I WONDER WHY.
- YOU'RE ONE TO TALK.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU WENT ON A DATE?
- I JUST HAVEN'T MET ANYBODY
WHO'S NOT COMPLETELY
SELF-ABSORBED
AND IMPOSSIBLE
TO HAVE A CONVERSATION WITH.
- IF THAT'S A VEILED CRITICISM
ABOUT ME,
I WON'T HEAR IT
AND I WON'T RESPOND TO IT.
- HMM.
MAYBE I'M WRONG.
- LATER THAT DAY MICHAEL
FINALIZED
THE SALE OF THE CORPORATE JET
AND WAS ALSO ABLE TO SOLVE THE
FAMILY'S TRANSPORTATION PROBLEM.
- HMM?
- I AM NOT RIDING
IN THAT THING.
- WELL, WE SOLD THE JET,
AND THEY DIDN'T WANT THIS.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
BESIDES, LINDSAY, IT'S NOT
LIKE YOU'RE MATERIALISTIC.
WELL, THEN,
IT'S ALL YOURS.
WATCH OUT FOR BRIDGES
AND HOP-ONS.
YOU'RE GONNA GET
SOME HOP-ONS.
- AND MICHAEL
WAS FINALLY PREPARED
TO BEGIN THE NEXT PHASE
OF THE FAMILY BUSINESS.
- WE GO TO TRISHA THOON
FOR MORE.
- AN ACTIVIST
KNOWN AS JOHNNY BARK
HAS TAKEN RESIDENCE
IN HIS BELOVED TREE
AND REFUSES TO COME DOWN.
WHAT IS HE PROTESTING?
THE EXPANSION OF HIGH-COST,
LOW-QUALITY MINI-MANSIONS
LIKE THIS ONE HERE.
[knocks on window,
glass shatters]
- YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
- MICHAEL MET WITH HIS SISTER
ABOUT THE ACTIVIST IN THE TREE.
- YOU WANT ME
TO GET HIM OUT?
- OH, COME ON,
IT'S ONE TREE.
LISTEN, AFTER WE
GET THAT LOT CLEARED,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE ENOUGH MONEY
FOR YOU TO NEUTER
THOUSANDS OF ANIMALS.
YOU CAN MAKE DOGS AND CATS
A COMPLETE THING OF THE PAST.
NO MORE DOGS AND CATS.
AND WE WILL HAVE
ENOUGH MONEY
FOR ME TO REPLACE THE STAIR CAR
WITH A NORMAL CAR.
- I'LL DO IT FOR THE CATS.
- MEANWHILE, MARTA'S INTERVIEW
WAS UNDERWAY,
AND GOB WAS GETTING
UNCOMFORTABLE
PLAYING THE SUPPORTIVE ROLE.
- I JUST TOLD HIM THAT
WE ARE THIS FAMILY NOW
AND THAT CAREER'S ONE THING,
BUT FAMILY IS FOREVER.
- I, TOO, HAVE
AN ANNOUNCEMENT TO MAKE.
TO PROVE THAT NO PRISON
CAN HOLD ME,
I WILL INCARCERATE MYSELF
IN THE PENITENTIARY
THAT HOLDS MY OWN FATHER,
ONLY TO ESCAPE
24 HOURS LATER.
NO SHACKLES
CAN HOLD THESE HANDS.
SAY THAT TO THEM IN SPANISH.
- THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL GOT A CALL
TO MEET GOB AT THE PRISON.
- YOU'RE GOING INTO PRISON?
I THOUGHT THERE WAS
SOMETHING WRONG WITH DAD.
- WHAT? NO, DAD'S FINE.
JUST SAW HIM IN THERE
THROWING THE BALL AROUND
WITH A COUPLE GUYS.
WHICH, OF COURSE,
HE NEVER DID WITH ME.
- HOW'D YOU EVEN GET THEM
TO AGREE TO THIS?
- OH, THE WARDEN'S A FAN.
- YOU REALLY THINK
YOU CAN BREAK OUT OF MY PRISON?
- YOU WON'T EVEN KNOW
I WAS HERE.
- THE WARDEN WAS INTRIGUED--
LESS ABOUT THE STUNT
AND MORE ABOUT THE PRISON
BEATINGS
THIS BRASH MAGICIAN
WAS SURE TO RECEIVE.
- ANY PRESS
IS GOOD PRESS, HUH?
- [Gob chuckling]
RIGHT.
- AND SO GOB WENT ABOUT
SWALLOWING THE KEY
TO PREPARE FOR HIS ESCAPE.
- [laughing]
THEN I PASS THE KEY,
BUST OUT OF PRISON
AND INTO MAGIC HISTORY.
OF COURSE, THAT IS
GONNA CONFLICT
WITH MY GOING TO THE DESIS
WITH MARTA.
- WELL, LIFE'S A COMPROMISE.
I PROBABLY WOULD HAVE
TAKEN HER TO THE NICE EVENT,
BUT PRISON'LL BE FUN TOO.
- THANK YOU.
I KNEW YOU'D COME THROUGH.
- COME THROUGH?
HOW'D I COME THROUGH?
GOB, HOW'D I COME THROUGH?
- YOU MIGHT WANNA FIND SOMETHING
A LITTLE STRONGER, WARDEN.
[electric zap]
[groans]
WHAT IS YOUR PROBLEM?
- MEANWHILE,
LINDSAY SET ABOUT
FULFILLING HER PROMISE
TO MICHAEL.
- GET OUT OF OUR
[bleep] TREE.
- AT THIS MOMENT, MAEBY FOUND
ANOTHER OPPORTUNITY TO REBEL.
- WE HAVE TO SAVE THIS TREE.
- WE HAVE TO!
- AND GEORGE SR. WAS ABOUT TO BE
SURPRISED BY HIS SON.
- KEEP YOUR ARM UP.
THAT'S HOW YOU GET ACCURACY.
- THOUGHT YOU SAID
THROWING THE BALL AGAINST THE
GARAGE DOOR BY YOURSELF
WAS HOW YOU GOT
ACCURACY.
- GOB,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- LIFE, DAD.
I KILLED A GUY.
NAH, IT'S JUST
A PUBLICITY STUNT.
I'M GONNA BUST OUT TOMORROW.
IMPRESSIVE, NO?
- YOU IDIOT. YOU'RE GONNA
GET YOURSELF KILLED.
- OH, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T REALIZE THERE
WEREN'T ANY MAGIC FANS HERE.
- HEY, WHITE POWER BILL,
HE'S ALL RIGHT.
- WHITE POWER BILL
CAN'T HEAR YOU
WITH SUCH DIRTY EARS.
- HEY, WHITE POWER BILL
HAS DIRTY EARS.
HEY, GUYS!
DIRTY EARS BILL!
- AND MICHAEL WAS ABOUT TO GET
A SURPRISE VISIT OF HIS OWN.
[doorbell rings]
[glass shatters]
- MICHAEL?
- YES? HI. I'M MICHAEL.
- I'M MARTA.
- YOU'RE MARTA?
- THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR TAKING ME TO THE AWARDS.
GOB SAID HE REALLY APPRECIATED
YOU COMING THROUGH FOR HIM.
- OH. SURE. YEAH.
THIS IS HOW
I CAME THROUGH, HUH?
LISTEN, MARTA--
- OH, AND I HOPE
YOU DON'T MIND DRIVING.
I TOOK A CAB HERE.
I JUST COULDN'T FIND MY KEYS.
- WELL, MY BROTHER
MAY HAVE EATEN THEM.
- [chuckles]
- LOOK--
UM...I HAVEN'T HIRED
A LIMO OR ANYTHING.
- I DON'T MIND.
- I THINK YOU MIGHT.
- [singing]
TOUCH OF MY FINGERS
WE'RE LIVIN'
IN YOUR WORLD NOW
THIS TIME
I'M GONNA BE DIFFERENT
- I'M AN ACTIVIST TOO.
I APPRECIATE WHAT YOU'RE
DOING FOR THE ENVIRONMENT.
BUT WE'RE NOT THE ONLY ONES
WHO DESTROY TREES.
WHAT ABOUT BEAVERS?
YOU CALL YOURSELF
AN ENVIRONMENTALIST?
WHY DON'T YOU
GO OUT AND CLUB SOME BEAVERS?
- YOU DON'T REALLY
GET NATURE, DO YA?
- IT WILL BE TORN DOWN,
WITH OR WITHOUT YOU.
WHERE ARE THE STAIRS?
- MEANWHILE, THE DESIS
WERE UNDERWAY.
- [speaking Spanish]
GUILLERMO ORTIZ
COMO EL RATON,
PABLO DOMINGUEZ
COMO PEPITO,
FELICIO COLO
COMO MIGUELITO--
- AND LUCILLE WAS MINGLING
WITH THE ELITE OF
THE LATINO TELEVISION ACADEMY.
- CAN I GET
A VODKA TONIC, PLEASE?
I'D LIKE A VODKA TONIC, PLEASE.
VODKA TONIC, PLEASE?
A SEA OF WAITERS, AND NO ONE
WILL TAKE A DRINK ORDER.
- BUSTER WAS ALSO MINGLING,
BUT, AT LUCILLE'S INSISTENCE,
WASN'T WEARING HIS GLASSES.
- COMO ESTOY?
EXCITING NIGHT.
[chuckles]
- AND LUCILLE BLUTH CROSSED
PATHS WITH LUCILLE AUSTERO.
- LUCILLE?
LUCILLE!
WELL, AREN'T YOU SOMETHING?
- OH!
- SHOWING UP HERE
WITHOUT YOUR HUSBAND.
SHAME BE DAMNED.
CAUTION TO THE WIND.
THAT'S JUST INCREDIBLE.
- THAT'S SO SWEET, DARLING.
I'M HERE TO SUPPORT YOU.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO'S ALL ALONE
AND LIKELY TO STAY THAT WAY.
MY HUSBAND'S
JUST A PHONE CALL AWAY.
- THAT'S ONE CALL PER DAY,
ISN'T IT?
GEE, I SHOULD THINK HE'D WANNA
SAVE THAT FOR HIS LAWYER.
- AT LEAST HE'S IN PRISON,
NOT AN URN.
- YOU ARE SO
DELICIOUSLY WITTY.
- AREN'T WE HAVING FUN?
- THE OTHER LUCILLE ALSO SUFFERS
FROM SEVERE VERTIGO.
- [singing] I'LL
FLY
AWAY
[applause]
- LUCILLE AUSTERO, MEANWHILE,
PERHAPS BECAUSE SHE'D NEVER SEEN
HIM WITHOUT HIS GLASSES,
FIRST TOOK NOTICE
OF BUSTER.
[Latin pop]
- [giggles]
- BUSTER, HOWEVER,
FAILED TO NOTICE HER,
AND SHE SENT HIM
A PROPOSITION.
- EXCUSE ME, SIR.
THIS IS FOR YOU.
- [giggles]
- [singing] I CAN'T SEE
ANYTHING BUT LOVE
- HUH?
- FINALLY, MARTA'S CATEGORY
WAS ANNOUNCED.
- Y EL DESI VA A...
[drumroll]
SANDRA ELENA HIGUERA.
[fanfare]
[orchestra continues]
- MARTA?
HEY.
I'M SORRY.
YOU REALLY DESERVED
TO WIN IN THERE.
DID YOU WIN?
I-I DON'T SPEAK SPANISH.
- IT'S NOT ABOUT THE AWARD.
IT'S CRAZY, BUT I THOUGHT
IT WOULD MAKE GOB PROUD.
- I'M SURE, IN HIS OWN WAY,
THAT HE'S--
- YOU KNOW, I JUST THINK
HE DOESN'T UNDERSTAND FAMILY,
YOU KNOW, COMMITMENT.
BUT THOSE ARE THE ONLY THINGS
THAT MATTER IN LIFE.
- AT THAT MOMENT MICHAEL
REALIZED THAT THIS WAS
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
HE'D EVER SEEN.
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE HE LOST HIS WIFE,
HE WANTED SOMEONE.
- [singing] TOUCH OF MY FINGERS
- [laughs]
- [singing] WE'RE LIVIN'
IN YOUR WORLD NOW
- AT THE SAME MOMENT,
GOB WAS READY TO RETRIEVE
THE KEY TO EXECUTE HIS ESCAPE.
- IS THERE
A PRIVATE BATHROOM NEARBY?
[clang]
- YOU'RE LOOKING AT IT.
- NO, NO, I CAN'T USE THAT.
NO, NO, I NEED PRIVACY.
YEAH, NO,
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN THAT WAY.
I CAN'T GO
WITHOUT PRIVACY.
I C--I CAN'T PASS THIS KEY
WITHOUT PRIVACY!
- WELL, I COULD ASK THE GUYS
TO LEAVE, BUT, UH,
THEY'VE, YOU KNOW, BEEN
LOCKING THE DOORS LATELY.
I--
- I'VE MADE
A HUGE MISTAKE.
- MICHAEL WAS HAVING
A WONDERFUL TIME WITH MARTA
AND DIDN'T WANT
THE EVENING TO END,
WHILE LINDSAY WAS BONDING
WITH THE MAN IN THE TREE.
- YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHAT IT'S
LIKE TO SAVE A LIVING THING.
- WELL, FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
I DO.
MY HUSBAND, TOBIAS, AND I
USED TO DO THIS KIND OF THING
ALL THE TIME.
I GUESS THAT'S WHY
I WAS SO ATTRACTED TO HIM.
HE WAS A SERIOUS AND COMMITTED
ADVOCATE FOR CHANGE.
- WHERE IS HE NOW?
- HE'S AT A WEEKEND
STAGE FIGHTING WORKSHOP
WITH CARL WEATHERS.
BUT HE USED TO
BELIEVE IN THINGS.
WE BOTH USED TO.
[door opens]
- SORRY, LINDSAY, I DIDN'T
REALIZE YOU WERE UP THERE.
- OH, I'M UP HERE, MIKE,
AND I'M NOT COMING DOWN!
I'M GONNA SAVE THIS TREE,
NO MATTER WHAT IT TAKES.
- OKAY. I'LL SEE YOU WHEN YOU
REALIZE WHAT THAT BUCKET'S FOR.
[door closes]
- YOU KNOW, I CAN SEE
WHY YOUR MOM LIKES IT.
IT IS A REALLY NICE TREE.
- WE'VE GOTTA
GET IT TORN DOWN.
- THAT MUST DIE.
STUPID TREE.
- BUSTER'S OUT OF CONTROL.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
ANOTHER PANIC ATTACK?
- ME?
NO.
SHE'S JUST WIGGED OUT
BECAUSE I HAVE A GIRLFRIEND.
- A WAITER HANDS HIM A NOTE;
SUDDENLY HE'S STEVE McQUEEN.
HE DOESN'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT SHE LOOKS LIKE.
- I KNOW SHE'S A BROWNISH AREA
WITH POINTS.
AND I KNOW I LOVE HER.
- I'M CALLING DR. MILLER.
- OKAY, I DON'T KNOW
I LOVE HER,
BUT I CANNOT TELL YOU
HOW LIBERATING IT IS
TO BE WITH SOMEONE
WHO'S NOT MOM,
WHO'S NOTHING LIKE HER.
- YEAH, AND YOU'RE JUST--
YOU'RE JUST JUMPING
RIGHT INTO THIS, HUH?
- OH, YES. YES.
THAT'S WHAT YOU DO
WHEN LIFE HANDS YOU A CHANCE
TO BE WITH SOMEONE SPECIAL.
YOU JUST GRAB THAT--THAT
BROWNISH AREA BY ITS POINTS,
AND YOU DON'T LET GO,
NO MATTER WHAT YOUR MOM SAYS.
MMM!
- GOOD TALK.
[phone rings]
HELLO.
- MICHAEL.
CHANGE OF ESCAPE PLAN.
I UNPLUGGED
THE ICE CREAM SANDWICH MACHINE,
AND THE GUARDS ARE ALL EATING
THEM BEFORE THEY GET TOO MELTY,
SO I'VE GOT
LIKE A HALF AN HOUR.
MEET ME AT THE SOUTH PRISON WALL
AND BRING THE STAIRS.
- MICHAEL KNEW HE HAD
AN OBLIGATION TO HIS BROTHER.
- [whispering]
MICHAEL!
- HEY, GOB!
- WHERE THE HELL
ARE THE STAIRS?
- OH!
I THOUGHT YOU WERE KIDDING!
HEY, SPEAKING OF KIDDING,
HOW SERIOUS ARE YOU
ABOUT MARTA?
I GET THE SENSE THAT THERE'S
NOT MUCH OF A FUTURE THERE.
AM I READING THAT RIGHT?
- LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
HOW WOULD YOU FEEL IF I
CAME DOWN ON YOU HARD?
- YOU'RE SAYING
I'M NOT READING THIS RIGHT.
- NO, I'M SAYING MOVE THE BIKE.
I NEED TO JUMP ON YOU
TO BREAK MY FALL.
- DON'T BE AN IDIOT.
DON'T JUMP ON ME.
- NO, I HAVE TO!
COME ON. STOP MOVING!
- COME ON!
DON'T JUMP ON ME!
- COME ON.
STOP MOVING!
- THE GUARDS SOON BECAME
CONCERNED
ABOUT THE PAPERWORK
THAT WOULD BE REQUIRED OF THEM
IF GOB ACTUALLY DID JUMP.
- DON'T BE SUCH A MORON!
- YOU'RE MAKING THIS
VERY, VERY DIFFICULT.
[electric zap]
OHH! GOD!
THIS IS PERSONAL--
- GOB.
GOB!
GOOD TALK.
- I'M A COMPLETE FAILURE.
- WHERE'D YOU GET
THAT KIND OF TALK?
- FROM YOU.
YOU ALWAYS SAY THAT
ABOUT ME.
- WELL, MAYBE YOU'RE NOT
ENTIRELY TO BLAME.
I HAVEN'T ALWAYS BEEN
THE BEST KIND OF FATHER EITHER.
- YOU'VE DONE A PRETTY GOOD JOB
OF BEING A FATHER
TO EVERYBODY IN HERE.
WHAT HAVE THEY GOT
THAT I DON'T?
YOU'VE NEVER EVEN...THROWN A
BALL AROUND WITH ME.
- GREAT.
NOW YOU'RE AN ATHLETE.
[sighs]
- [snoring]
- LINDSAY LEFT THE TREE
TO SLEEP IN HER OWN BED,
AND JOHNNY BARK LEFT THE TREE
TO AWAKEN HER.
- SO, LINDSAY, I WAS THINKING--
- JOHNNY BARK?
- I WANNA BE WITH YOU,
LINDSAY.
- WHAT?
- AND I KNOW YOU WANNA
BE WITH ME TOO.
- NO, I DON'T.
- BUT ALL THE THINGS
YOU SAID ABOUT COMMITMENT
AND BELIEVING IN THINGS--
THAT'S THE WAY I FEEL!
- JOHNNY, I'M SORRY. I--
I DIDN'T MEAN TO LEAD YOU ON.
I THINK YOU'RE GROSS.
[tree falls]
- UH-OH.
- MY TREE.
THAT'S WHY YOU NEVER
GET OUT OF THE TREE.
- AND GOB WAS ABOUT TO GET A
REASON TO STAY IN PRISON.
[rock music]
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
- NOT GREAT.
- [singing] A MOMENT OF STEEL
A DRY-EYED HOUSE
- MAYBE THIS'LL HELP.
- AND FOR THE FIRST TIME,
GOB HAD THE GAME OF CATCH
WITH HIS FATHER
HE'D BEEN WAITING FOR
HIS WHOLE LIFE.
- OKAY, READY?
PUT YOUR MITT UP.
- [singing]
THE TEARS OF AN ANGEL
THE TEARS OF A DOVE
- THERE YOU GO.
- [singing] CRY LOVE
- WHITE POWER!
- [groaning]
I'M...WHITE.
- AND MICHAEL DECIDED TO
SHARE HIS FEELINGS WITH MARTA.
- MICHAEL.
- MARTA.
I'M NOT REALLY QUITE SURE
HOW TO SAY THIS, BUT, UM--
[phone ringing]
I HAD A GREAT TIME
LAST NIGHT.
- I DID TOO.
- AND, UM...
[phone continues ringing]
WE'RE SO IN SYNCH
ON SO MANY THINGS,
AND, UH, I-I--
[phone continues ringing]
[sighs) YOU GUYS DON'T HAVE
A MACHINE, HUH?
- SORRY. [giggling]
- OKAY.
- HELLO.
OH, MY GOD.
GOB HAS BEEN
STABBED IN THE BACK.
- AM I STILL IN PRISON?
- YOU'RE IN THE HOSPITAL.
- TA-DAH.
- MEANWHILE, BUSTER
WAS WAITING IN THE HALLWAY.
- BUSTER?
- OH, MISS AUSTERO.
WH-WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- A TOUCH OF THE DIZZIES.
- OH. OH.
- SO, LISTEN, BUSTER,
HAVE YOU GIVEN ANY, UH,
THOUGHT TO MY OFFER?
- [stammers]
I'M SORRY. WHAT?
- WELL, I MEAN, MY PHONE
HASN'T MADE A PEEP.
- HA--HAS YOUR HAIR
ALWAYS BEEN THAT POINTY,
MISS AUSTERO?
- IT'S LUCILLE.
- RIGHT. RIGHT.
THAT'S MY MOM'S NAME.
- YES!
[laughing]
- [whimpering]
OH, GOD!
- BUSTER? BUSTER! BU--
HE--OH!
[groans]
I'M ALL RIGHT.
- HE'S FINE.
I'LL BE IN THE HOSPITAL BAR.
- UH, YOU KNOW, THERE ISN'T
A HOSPITAL BAR, MOTHER.
- WELL, THIS IS WHY
PEOPLE HATE HOSPITALS.
[Lucille cackling]
[cackling continues]
- YOU WERE RIGHT, MICHAEL.
LIFE IS TOO SHORT.
MINE ALMOST ENDED TODAY.
SO I THINK I'M GONNA
WORK THINGS OUT WITH MARTA.
- YOU ARE, HUH?
- YEAH.
- BOY, THAT'S, UH--
THAT'S GREAT.
- HMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S FUNNY?
- MMM.
I WAS GONNA WALK OUT
OF THAT PRISON LAST NIGHT
AND BREAK UP WITH HER.
GOOD THING YOU DIDN'T
BRING THE STAIRS, HUH?
- MMM. VERY FUNNY. YEAH.
IT'S HYSTERICAL.
I'M LUCKY.
- CAN I COME IN NOW?
- YEAH, SURE.
HE'S FINE.
- LISTEN, I REALLY APPRECIATE
YOU HELPING ME OUT LAST NIGHT.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
YOU GOTTA PUT FAMILY FIRST.
THAT'S THE STUPID THING
THAT I BELIEVE.
- YOU TWO KEEP TALKING
OUT THERE,
I'M GONNA
START GETTING JEALOUS.
- I WAS REALLY WORRIED
ABOUT YOU.
- YOU'VE GOT NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
WE'RE GONNA BE TOGETHER
FOR A LONG TIME.
- WE'RE FAMILY NOW.
I AM SO HAPPY.
[giggling]
I'M GONNA CALL THE KIDS.
- [singing] TO GO ALONE
BUT THIS WAS A MARRIAGE
OF SPIRIT AND FLESH AND BONE
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
- [singing] CRY LOVE
CRY LOVE
THE TEARS OF AN ANGEL
THE TEARS OF A DOVE
CRY LOVE
- ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT,"
GOB LEARNS HOW HE SURVIVED
HIS STABBING.
- LOOKS LIKE THE SHIV WOULD HAVE
DONE SOME REAL DAMAGE
IF IT HADN'T BEEN FOR THIS.
IT WAS IN
YOUR LOWER INTESTINE.
- SO CLOSE.
- AND BUSTER
MAKES A BOLD MOVE.
[knocking]
- BUSTER.
- LET'S GO FOR IT.