male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH ALWAYS
RODE HIS BIKE TO WORK,
BUT THE RECENT HEAT WAVE HAD
TAKEN SOME OF THE FUN OUT OF IT.
IT HAD ALSO CAUSED PROBLEMS
IN HIS PRESENTATION TO
THE BLUTH COMPANY INVESTORS.
- THERE'S NO SCREWUPS
WITH THE PERMITS THIS TIME?
- THE PERMITS HAVE BEEN FILED
ABSOLUTELY ON TIME.
YOU HAVE MY WORD ON THAT.
UM, TELL YOU WHAT.
LET ME GET
SOME OF THIS, UH--
WELL, AS YOU CAN--
THE IMPORTANT PART IS HERE.
- BYE, YOU GUYS.
REALLY GREAT TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
THEY THINK YOU'RE
FULL OF [bleep]
I THINK IT'S THE SWEATING.
- I'VE GOTTA GET A CAR.
- DON'T WORRY.
I TOLD THEM THE TRUTH.
- THAT I RODE HERE ON A BIKE?
- THAT THE PERMITS
WEREN'T FILED.
- BUT MY DAD FILED THE PERMITS
BEFORE HE WENT TO JAIL.
- HE MOST CERTAINLY DID NOT.
- SO I JUST LIED
TO THE INVESTORS?
- YOU MOST CERTAINLY DID.
- THAT'S REALLY GREAT.
NOW I GOTTA RIDE MY BIKE
OUT TO THE PRISON
AND TALK TO MY DAD.
THAT'LL BE FUN
IN 100-DEGREE HEAT.
- WHY DON'T YOU TAKE
YOUR DAD'S CAR?
- NO.
DAD WOULD NEVER GO FOR THAT.
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
THERE'S NO ICE CREAM
IN THE CAR.
- I'LL BE CAREFUL.
ALL RIGHT, THIS IS
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO.
CAREFUL, MICHAEL.
OH.
- WHATEVER YOU THINK.
- YEAH.
- BUT I DID SEE GOB
DRIVING IT LAST WEEK.
- WAIT, HONESTLY,
GOB'S DRIVING THE CAR?
- I'M NOT THE LIAR.
narrator: MICHAEL NEEDED
HIS FATHER'S CAR,
SO HE WENT TO CONFRONT
HIS BROTHER GOB.
- GIVE ME A GOB.
- GOB!
- NO, I DIDN'T MEAN FOR YOU
TO YELL MY NAME AT ME.
IT'S WHAT I CALL
A DOUBLE-DIPPED BANANA
WITH EVERYTHING ON IT.
- HEY, I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU.
I ASKED YOU TWO WEEKS AGO
WHETHER WE SHOULD USE DAD'S CAR,
AND YOU SAID IT
WOULD BE BAD FORM.
NOW I HEAR YOU'RE DRIVING IT.
- THAT IS A LIE,
A BOLD-FACED LIE!
narrator:
GOB WAS LYING.
HE HAD BEEN DRIVING
HIS FATHER'S CAR.
- WHY DON'T YOU JUST TAKE
YOUR PRECIOUS
PORTABLE STAIRWAY VEHICLE
YOU'RE ALWAYS TRYING
TO CONVINCE US IS A CAR?
- YEAH, THAT WOULD BE GREAT,
EXCEPT OUR BROTHER-IN-LAW
LEFT IT IN
AN AIRPORT PARKING LOT.
- FROM WHENCE IT CAME, HUH?
narrator: IN FACT,
TOBIAS HAD INTENDED
TO PARK THE FAMILY'S
ONLY VEHICLE
AT THE AIRPORT PARKING LOT
BUT WAS WAVED ON
TO THE TARMAC INSTEAD,
WHERE HE FOUND A SPOT
CLOSE TO HIS GATE.
- HERE YOU GO, UNCLE GOB.
I HAD TO USE TWO STICKS
TO SUPPORT ALL
THE EXTRA CHOCOLATE AND NUTS.
- HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
WHOA.
TWO STICKS AND EXTRA CHOCOLATE?
IS IT MARDI GRAS?
WHAT ARE YOU CHARGING FOR THAT?
- HE DOESN'T LIKE
TO DISCUSS MONEY.
- I DON'T LIKE TO DISCUSS MONEY.
- WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
YOU DON'T PAY FOR IT?
- A BLUTH BANANA?
NO, I HADN'T PLANNED ON IT.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
IF YOU WANT TO USE MY LIKENESS
FOR A HAMBURGLAR-TYPE
CHARACTER,
I'LL SIGN OFF ON THAT,
MR. BANANA-GRABBER.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO MORE BANANA GRABBING.
NO MORE CAR GRABBING.
THROW THAT AWAY, PLEASE.
- BUT IT'S ALREADY MADE.
- I DON'T CARE.
NOBODY GETS IT NOW, OKAY?
ARE YOU HAPPY?
- MY OWN BROTHER, MICHAEL.
MY OWN SELFISH BROTHER.
MICHAEL.
- ALL RIGHT.
I DO NOT WANT YOU TO GET UPSET.
HE DID NOT MEAN THAT.
SOMETIMES HE SAYS--
- SELFISH MICHAEL.
- HE DID NOT MEAN THAT EITHER.
narrator: MICHAEL THEN WENT
TO HIS SISTER
TO FIND HIS FATHER'S CAR.
- WHAT CAR?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
- DAD'S CAR. THE ONE YOU DIDN'T
TELL ME THAT YOU HAD,
EVEN THOUGH I HAD TO RIDE
MY BICYCLE TO WORK ALL WEEK.
- OH, DAD'S CAR.
WELL, OBVIOUSLY I'M GONNA USE IT
IF IT'S AN EMERGENCY.
narrator:
LINDSAY HAD SUCH AN EMERGENCY
THREE DAYS EARLIER
WHEN HER SALON WAS ABLE
TO SQUEEZE HER IN
AT THE LAST MOMENT.
- [gasps]
THAT COLOR'S DISCONTINUED!
I HAVE TO GET READY
FOR THE BACHELORETTE AUCTION.
- THE BACHELORETTE AUCTION?
YOU KNOW YOU'RE MARRIED.
- YOU JUST GO TO DINNER
WITH THE GUY.
IT'S FOR CHARITY.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU SAID
ABOUT POSING
FOR THE "LADIES OF LITERACY"
CALENDAR,
THE ONE WITH THE PICTURES
OF ALL THE 30-YEAR-OLD WOMEN
IN LINGERIE
WITH THEIR NIPPLES COVERED
BY COPIES OF OLIVER TWIST.
YEAH, THAT MADE A BIG DIFFERENCE
FOR THE YOUNG ONES.
- IT WOULD HAVE IF IT DIDN'T
GET BANNED FROM THE SCHOOLS.
- COME ON, FACE IT.
YOU DO ALL THIS CHARITY CRAP
JUST TO STROKE YOUR EGO.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT THE AUCTION'S FOR TONIGHT.
- THE WETLANDS.
- TO DO WHAT WITH THEM?
- DRY THEM.
- SAVE THEM.
- FROM DRYING, WHICH IS MORE
THAN YOU WOULD EVER DO.
YOU'RE, LIKE, THE LEAST
CHARITABLE PERSON I KNOW.
- I DON'T DO
ANYTHING FOR MYSELF.
EVERYTHING THAT I DO
IS FOR THIS FAMILY.
- OH, YOU DON'T DO IT
FOR US, MICHAEL.
YOU JUST DO IT BECAUSE YOU LOVE
BEING THE GUY IN CHARGE,
'CAUSE YOU LOVE SAYING NO,
LIKE YOU SAID TO GOB
WHEN HE WANTED A FROZEN BANANA,
AND EVEN AFTER
HE GAVE YOU THE RIGHTS
TO HIS
MR. BANANA-GRABBER CHARACTER.
- YOU KNOW WHAT, I WILL START
DOING MY CHARITY WORK
WHEN YOU START DOING YOURS.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WHERE'S THE CAR?
- I THINK BUSTER HAS IT.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S ON THE SCHEDULE.
- THERE IS A SCHEDULE?
I ALWAYS TRY SO HARD
NOT TO LOOK AT THIS THING.
narrator: SO MICHAEL
WENT TO FIND BUSTER.
- WHO LET YOU IN?
- YOUR NEW CLEANING WOMAN.
WHAT HAPPENED TO LUZ?
- SUPPOSEDLY,
LUZ HAD TO TAKE HER DAUGHTER
TO THE HOSPITAL.
THAT'S LUPE, HER SISTER.
- GOD, I HOPE SHE'S OKAY.
- SHE'S AWFUL.
CAN BARELY WASH A DISH.
UH-OH, SHE BETTER NOT
WALK THROUGH HERE
AFTER SHE'S BEEN IN THERE.
TELL ME YOU'VE GOT
AN EXIT STRATEGY.
- MOTHER.
- OH, PLEASE.
THEY DIDN'T SNEAK INTO THIS
COUNTRY TO BE YOUR FRIENDS.
- WOW.
- DON'T YOU JUDGE ME.
YOU'RE THE SELFISH ONE.
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO CHARGED HIS OWN BROTHER
FOR A BLUTH FROZEN BANANA.
I MEAN, IT'S ONE BANANA,
MICHAEL.
WHAT COULD IT COST, $10?
- YOU'VE NEVER ACTUALLY SET FOOT
IN A SUPERMARKET, HAVE YOU?
- I DON'T HAVE TIME FOR THIS.
I'VE GOT TO GET READY
FOR THE BACHELORETTE AUCTION.
- YOU'RE DOING THAT?
YOU CAN'T POSSIBLY TELL ME THAT
YOU CARE ABOUT THE WETLANDS.
- I CARE ABOUT GOING FOR MORE
MONEY THAN LUCILLE AUSTERO.
narrator: IN FACT, LUCILLE BLUTH
HAD MADE SURE OF THAT.
- LUCILLE!
- I GOT YOU TICKETS
TO "THE PRODUCERS."
I ALREADY SAW IT IN NEW YORK.
BUT THAT'S OF NO USE TO A WOMAN
WHOSE VERTIGO MAKES FLYING
A GROTESQUE MISADVENTURE.
- YOU MUST HAVE SCRIMPED
AND SAVED FOR THESE.
BUT ISN'T THIS
THE NIGHT OF THE AUCTION?
- IS IT?
- YOU SEEM PRETTY CONFIDENT.
- OH, I THINK THERE'S
A CERTAIN BACHELOR
WHO WON'T MIND COMING HOME WITH
ME AT THE END OF THE EVENING.
- BUSTER?
- WHERE DID HE GO?
BUSTER!
WHY DO YOU HIDE
EVERY TIME THE DOORBELL RINGS?
- I'M NOT HIDING.
narrator: BUSTER WAS HIDING
FROM LUCILLE AUSTERO.
AFTER INADVERTENTLY FLIRTING
WITH HER AT A SOCIAL EVENT
WHILE NOT WEARING HIS GLASSES,
LUCILLE HAD BEEN
PURSUING HIM EVER SINCE.
- BUSTER, HI.
IT'S ME AGAIN.
- [gasping]
I'VE STILL GOT THOSE
"PRODUCERS" TICKETS,
AND I'D LOVE
TO SHARE THEM WITH YOU.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO THINK
I'M TAKING THIS MORE
SERIOUSLY THAN YOU ARE,
AND UNLESS YOU'RE PLANNING
SOME GRAND ROMANTIC GESTURE,
MY FEELINGS ARE JUST
THE TEENSIEST BIT HURT.
- WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
- BID ON YOU.
- HOW MUCH?
- $10,000.
- WHEN?
- WHEN THEY CALL MY NAME.
- NO, THEY'RE NOT
GOING TO CALL YOUR NAME.
THEY'RE GOING TO CALL MY NAME.
[sighs]
GOOD GRIEF.
- HEY, BUSTY.
YOU BEEN USING DAD'S CAR?
- NO.
UH, WELL, YES.
- YOU GOT THE KEYS?
- UH, PROBABLY
IN MY SCHOOL PANTS
- OKAY.
- I HAVE BEEN A PART OF
THIS ARCHEOLOGICAL DIG.
I THINK WE FOUND A PART
OF A PTERODACTYL
UNDER FASHION ISLAND.
- BE CAREFUL.
[gasps]
- OH...
THAT--THAT WAS 90% GRAVITY.
IT IS MY DAY ON THE SCHEDULE,
BUT I GUESS YOU GET THEM FIRST.
- YEAH.
- WAIT, I NEED
MY RAPE WHISTLE BACK.
- YOU GOT ALL YOUR STUFF
OUT OF THE CAR?
- YEAH, I LEFT MY, UM, HOMEWORK
IN THE BACKSEAT,
BUT I CAN GET IT LATER.
- OKAY.
[whistle blows]
[chuckles]
HELP.
narrator:
MICHAEL SURVEYED THE DAMAGE
TO HIS FATHER'S CAR--
THE PARTIALLY EXCAVATED SKULL,
THE SPILLED NAIL POLISH,
THE BURNED SEATS--
AND HE CAME TO
AN IMPORTANT DECISION.
- WELL, I'M GETTING
SOME ICE CREAM.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT RIGHT NOW.
narrator: MICHAEL, NOW ABLE
TO DRIVE TO PRISON,
CONFRONTED HIS FATHER
ABOUT THE PERMITS.
- HOW COME YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
THAT YOU DIDN'T FILE THEM?
- I'M UNDER A LOT OF PRESSURE.
I'M TRYING TO GET MY NEWSLETTER
OFF THE GROUND,
AND I'M TRYING TO DECIDE
WHICH GANG TO ALIGN MYSELF WITH.
- IS IT PLEDGE WEEK ALREADY?
- I'VE GOT IT DOWN TO TWO,
BUT, HONESTLY, I JUST
DON'T EVEN WANT TO CHOOSE.
I JUST FEEL--
I FEEL LIKE THE PRETTIEST GIRL
AT THE DANCE.
LISTEN, ABOUT THAT PERMIT THING,
THAT'S AN EASY FIX.
JUST BREAK
INTO THE PERMIT OFFICE,
SLIP THE APPLICATION
INTO THE NEXT FILE,
THEN YOU TELL THEM, YOU KNOW,
"HEY, YOU GUYS SCREWED UP."
- I'M NOT DOING THAT, DAD.
- MICHAEL, YOU LIED
TO YOUR INVESTORS.
YOU GOTTA MAKE THAT RIGHT.
CALL GOB.
HE'LL HANDLE IT.
THAT'S WHAT--
THAT'S WHAT HE'S FOR.
- THAT'S WHAT HE'S FOR.
- YOU BETTER TELL HIM
I'M ASKING.
I DON'T THINK HE'S
GONNA DO IT FOR YOU
AFTER YOU WOULDN'T EVEN GIVE HIM
A FROZEN BANANA, MICHAEL?
- WHAT IS THERE,
A CHAT ROOM THAT YOU GUYS--
- THAT IS NOT CHARITABLE.
- NEVER MIND.
I'LL TELL GOB THAT
YOU WANT HIM TO DO THIS.
- OKAY, I GOT A DANCE
I GOTTA GET READY FOR.
- WHOA, THERE'S REALLY A DANCE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
BOTH SIDES ARE MAKING
A LOT OF PROMISES.
- YOU SHOULD CALL THIS
A GOB, GUY.
[crunching and cracking]
- GOB, CAN I TALK
TO YOU FOR A SEC?
LISTEN, UM, I'M REALLY SORRY
ABOUT BEFORE.
I SAID SOME THINGS,
AND I GOT A LITTLE CARRIED AWAY.
IT'S NOT THE WAY YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO TREAT A BROTHER,
ESPECIALLY ONE
THAT I VALUE SO HIGHLY.
OH, I NEED A FAVOR.
- THAT WAS SUBTLE.
[whistle]
- DID YOU JUST WHISTLE?
- I HAD TO BUY A CANDIED APPLE
WHEN YOU DENIED ME A BANANA,
SO, YEAH, I'M WHISTLING.
SATISFIED?
IT'S NOT THAT NOTICEABLE.
LISTEN.
DAD WOULD LIKE FOR YOU
TO BREAK INTO THE PERMIT OFFICE.
- DAD?
DAD SAID HE WANTED ME FOR THAT?
- YES, HE DID.
WILL YOU DO IT?
- MAYBE.
I HAVE SOME CONDITIONS.
[whistling]
TERMS.
- BOY.
- ONE CONDITION AND ONE TERM.
- ALL RIGHT.
LET'S HAVE
THE CONDITION FIRST.
- FREE BANANA WHENEVER I WANT.
- SINGLE DIP.
- DOUBLE DIP,
BUT I'LL TAKE ONE STICK.
- ALL RIGHT. WHAT ELSE?
- CREATIVE CONTROL,
SPIN-OFF RIGHTS,
AND THEME PARK APPROVAL
FOR MR. BANANA-GRABBER,
BABY BANANA-GRABBER,
AND ANY OTHER
BANANA-GRABBER FAMILY CHARACTER
THAT MIGHT EMANATE THEREFROM.
- I RETAIN ANIMATION RIGHTS,
AND WE'RE GONNA
GO BACK TO SINGLE DIP.
- DONE.
- GREAT. WHAT ELSE?
- YOU HUMILIATED ME
IN FRONT OF MY NEPHEW.
I EXPECT YOU TO FIX THAT.
I WANT THE RESPECT
OF YOUR SON.
- YOU BETTER LET ME
DO THE TALKING.
GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOUR UNCLE HAS A REQUEST.
- ONE BLUTH BANANA,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
- GO AHEAD, GIVE IT TO HIM.
GOB DESERVES YOUR RESPECT,
AND FROM NOW ON,
I WANT YOU TO DO WHATEVER
HE ASKS YOU TO DO, OKAY?
AFTER ALL, HE IS YOUR UNCLE,
AND I THINK WE OUGHT
TO JUST EMBRACE THAT.
- THANK YOU.
- HAVE I HELD UP
MY END OF THE DEAL?
- I CAN'T BELIEVE I GAVE YOU
ANIMATION RIGHTS.
MAN, I HOPE THAT DOESN'T COME
BACK AND BITE ME IN THE ASS.
narrator:
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY,
WANTING TO PROVE TO MICHAEL THAT
SHE WAS A CHARITABLE PERSON,
JOINED A GROUP OF ACTIVISTS
DEDICATED TO
PRESERVING THE WETLANDS.
- YEAH, HI,
I'M GONNA NEED A TAXI.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT SMELL
IS YOU, THE CAR,
SOMETHING YOU ATE,
OR SOMETHING
YOU'RE ABOUT TO EAT,
BUT MY GOD,
YOU'RE IN A SERVICE BUSINESS!
[phone ringing]
- HELLO.
- I'M IN THE WETLANDS.
I'VE GOT A POKER THING,
AND I'M GONNA CLEAN THEM UP.
SO THE NEXT TIME YOU WANNA
TELL ME THAT I'M UNCHARITABLE,
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
ASK YOURSELF
WHO CALLED YOU
FROM THE WETLANDS?
- WHO IS THIS?
- NICE TRY.
YOU'RE THE SELFISH ONE.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I'VE GOT SOME NATURE TO SAVE.
[loud croak]
[screams]
narrator: WHILE LINDSAY
WAS FINDING IT DIFFICULT
TO BE TRULY CHARITABLE,
MICHAEL WAS LOOKING
FOR AN OPPORTUNITY
TO RISE TO LINDSAY'S CHALLENGE,
AND THAT'S WHEN HE RECOGNIZED
HIS MOTHER'S FILL-IN HOUSEKEEPER
AT A BUS STOP.
- HELLO THERE.
YOU'RE NOT RIDING THE BUS TODAY.
GET IN THIS CAR.
I'M NOT TAKING NO
FOR AN ANSWER--COME ON.
DON'T MAKE ME GET OUT
OF THIS CAR
AND PUT YOU IN HERE MYSELF.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
THE WOMAN HE PICKED UP
WASN'T LUPE,
BUT WAS A TOTAL STRANGER.
AND UPON SEEING BONES,
A SHOVEL,
AND WHAT
APPEARED TO BE BLOOD,
SHE REALIZED HE WASN'T
WHO SHE THOUGHT HE WAS.
- MISTER, PLEASE.
[speaking Spanish]
- THIS IS GONNA BE TRICKY.
I DON'T SPEAK SPANISH.
- YO "ESCARED."
- "IZQUIERDO."
I KNOW THAT ONE.
LEFT TURN IT IS, MRS.--
THEY CALL ME SELFISH.
narrator: MICHAEL THOUGHT
HE WAS HELPING
HIS MOTHER'S HOUSEKEEPER,
BUT HE HAD THE WRONG WOMAN.
- I GUESS IT WOULD JUST
BE A GUY WHO,
YOU KNOW,
GRABS BANANAS AND RUNS...
OR, UH, A BANANA
THAT GRABS THINGS.
I DON'T KNOW.
WHY WOULD A BANANA
GRAB ANOTHER BANANA?
THOSE ARE THE KIND OF QUESTIONS
I DON'T WANNA ANSWER.
[phone ringing]
HELLO.
- OH, MICHAEL,
IT'S SO BEAUTIFUL HERE.
YOU HAVE TO COME DOWN
AND SEE THIS.
- WELL, I'M A LITTLE BUSY
RIGHT NOW.
I'VE GOT SOMEONE ELSE
IN THE CAR WITH ME,
AND I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE
UNTIL SHE'S TAKEN CARE OF.
- LOOK, I SCREWED UP, OKAY?
I'M LOST, AND I HATE THEM.
I HATE THE WETLANDS.
THEY'RE STUPID AND WET,
AND THERE ARE BUGS EVERYWHERE.
AND I THINK I MACED A CRANE,
MICHAEL.
LOOK, YOU'VE GOT DAD'S CAR.
WHY DON'T YOU COME PICK ME UP?
- CRAZY.
LOCO.
LISTEN, WE GOTTA MAKE
A LITTLE DETOUR, OKAY?
SO I HOPE NO ONE'S
WAITING FOR YOU.
narrator: IN FACT, THE WOMAN
MICHAEL THOUGHT WAS LUPE
DID HAVE PEOPLE
WAITING FOR HER...
[sirens wailing]
AND THEY HAD
REPORTED HER MISSING.
THE REAL LUPE, HOWEVER,
WAS LEAVING LUCILLE'S
FOR THE EVENING.
- OH!
BUSTER, I--
OH.
HELLO.
IT APPEARS MY
ONE-TIME ADMIRER
IS NOT PLANNING SOME GRAND
ROMANTIC GESTURE AFTER ALL.
[chuckles] YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT'S HIS LOSS.
IT'S HIS LOSS!
narrator:
GOB, MEANWHILE,
WAS CASING THE PERMIT OFFICE,
FOLLOWING THE FIRST RULE
OF SURVEILLANCE--
NEVER GET NOTICED.
- CARRIER EXPRESS.
[whistles]
[dog barking]
- SAY, YOU'RE NOT
OUR REGULAR GUY.
- NO, I'M THE SUBSTITUTE.
[whistles]
- HEY, GARY,
GET A PICTURE OF ME
WITH THE NEW
WHISTLING DELIVERY GUY.
narrator: GOB REALIZED
HE NEEDED A NEW PLAN.
- SO I NEED YOU TO GIVE
YOUR FATHER A MESSAGE FOR ME.
ALL RIGHT. YOU HEARD MY DAD.
I HAVE TO DO WHATEVER
YOU ASK ME TO.
RIGHT.
I FORGOT ABOUT THAT.
ALL RIGHT, TAKE THIS
LOCK-PICK SET,
BREAK INTO
THE PERMIT OFFICE FOR ME.
- NO, I THINK I BETTER CHECK
WITH MY DAD FIRST.
WELL--
- YOU'RE GONNA BREAK INTO
A PERMIT OFFICE?
SWEET. CAN I COME?
narrator:
AND GEORGE MICHAEL SAW A CHANCE
TO GET CLOSER TO MAEBY.
- YOU KNOW, MY DAD HATES
TO MICROMANAGE.
LET'S JUST DO THIS.
narrator:
AND BACK AT THE WETLANDS,
LINDSAY FINALLY FOUND HER TAXI.
- OH, GOOD LORD.
YOU SMELL WORSE THAN BEFORE.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S ME!
narrator: AND IN HER HASTE
TO LEAVE THE WETLANDS,
SHE FORGOT TO CALL MICHAEL.
- HEY.
HEY! STAY THERE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GET IN THE CAR.
DON'T MOVE.
LINDSAY! LINDS!
COME ON.
I'M TIRED OF LOOKING.
SHE'S NOT HERE.
SHE PROBABLY NEVER WAS HERE.
SHE SET ME UP.
THIS IS PROBABLY
ALL ABOUT THE CAR.
I'M GONNA KILL HER!
HEY! WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
HELLO!
I'M TRYING TO HELP YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
GOB MET WITH HIS FATHER
TO DISCUSS
THE PERMIT OFFICE BREAK-IN.
SO I SAY TO MICHAEL,
"IF IT'S SO IMPORTANT TO DAD--
[whistling]
I'LL LOOK PAST YOUR SELFISHNESS
AND DO IT."
- THERE'S A DENTIST IN HERE
WHO, UH, TOOK LIBERTIES
WITH HIS PATIENTS.
I'M GONNA ASK HIM TO LOOK AT
WHATEVER IS HAPPENING WITH YOU.
- THANKS, POP.
HEY, MY STOCK IS NEVER
GONNA BE HIGHER
WITH HIS
GANG THAN IT IS RIGHT NOW.
- YEAH, SO HAVE YOU,
UH, MADE A DECISION OR--
- [sighs]
I DON'T KNOW.
I THOUGHT I HAD IT DOWN TO TWO,
BUT THEN THE HAITIANS
MADE THIS BEAUTIFUL PITCH.
SO, UH, ANY TROUBLE
AT THE, UH, PERMIT OFFICE?
- NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO, NO.
- EASY.
- I DELEGATED,
JUST LIKE YOU TAUGHT ME.
- WHO'D YOU GET?
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
- MY GRANDSON?
- YEAH.
- YOU GOT MY 14-YEAR-OLD
GRANDSON TO DO THIS.
- UNDER 18,
WALKS OUT CLEAN.
- LISTEN, UM,
THERE'S A VERY STRICT
"NO TOUCHING" POLICY HERE, BUT--
OH, WHAT THE HELL, IT'S WORTH
A WEEK IN THE HOTBOX.
- NO TOUCHING!
- YOU STUPID ASS.
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS SUCCESSFUL
WITH THE LOCK PICK
GOB HAD GIVEN HIM.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO PUT THE FORM
IN THE WRONG FILE.
- I KNOW; I'M JUST
LEAVING MY CALLING CARD.
- I THOUGHT WE DIDN'T WANT
ANYONE TO KNOW WE WERE HERE.
- IT'S A LITTLE LATE FOR THAT.
OUR FINGERPRINTS ARE EVERYWHERE.
- YOU SAID THEY WEREN'T
GONNA CHECK FOR FINGERPRINTS.
- NO, I SAID DON'T
WEAR YOUR MITTENS.
I DIDN'T WANT YOU TO LOOK STUPID
ON THE SECURITY CAMERA.
- THERE'S A SECURITY CAMERA?
- SECURITY BREACH.
- SOMEONE'S COMING.
WHAT DO WE DO?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I ALWAYS GET CAUGHT.
- SAVE YOURSELF.
I'LL TAKE THE HIT.
MY RECORD'S CLEAN.
WELL, I GOT MY BIKE SEAT
STOLEN ONCE,
BUT I DON'T THINK IT COUNTS
ON YOUR RECORD
IF YOU'RE THE VICTIM.
THERE IS A RECORD OF THIS,
BUT IT'S NOT LIKE I'M--
- THANKS, I'LL TAKE THE RAP
NEXT TIME WE DO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, OKAY?
- NEXT TIME.
[door opens]
- HOLD IT!
narrator:
AND LINDSAY MADE IT
TO THE SAVE THE WETLANDS AUCTION
WITH MOMENTS TO SPARE.
- OH, HONEY.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO SHOW UP
AS THE WETLANDS.
narrator: WHILE LUCILLE
WAS WAITING FOR BUSTER
TO SHOW UP AND BID ON HER,
BUSTER WAS WAITING FOR
THE OTHER LUCILLE TO LEAVE
FOR WHAT HE ASSUMED
WAS "THE PRODUCERS,"
BUT WAS NOW, IN FACT,
THE BACHELORETTE AUCTION.
AND LINDSAY WAS FINALLY
UP FOR AUCTION,
WHICH MICHAEL ARRIVED
JUST IN TIME TO SEE.
WHAT DO I HEAR
FOR LINDSAY BLUTH?
GENTLEMEN, IT'S A GOOD CAUSE.
narrator: AND AS MICHAEL
LOOKED AT HIS SISTER,
UNCERTAIN WHETHER
HER FACE WAS RED
FROM EMBARRASSMENT
OR THE SUN DAMAGE,
IT WAS CLEAR SHE HAD BEEN
IN THE WETLANDS THAT DAY.
- ONE THOUSAND.
- [people gasping]
- SERIOUSLY?
SOLD...TO THE MAN
WHO TRULY KNOWS WHAT CHARITY IS.
- AND NOW, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE LOVELY LUCILLE.
- MOVE! MOVE! MOVE! MOVE!
- WHO IS THE LUCKY BACHELOR--
narrator: AND BUSTER
SHOWED UP JUST IN TIME--
TEN THOUSAND DOLLARS!
[gasps]
- [singing]
IT HAD TO BE YOU
- BUSTER!
narrator:
TO BID ON THE WRONG LUCILLE.
- [gasping]
- HOW GRAND!
- [stammers]
- HOW TERRIBLY GRAND!
- [whimpers]
- [sighs]
- WELL, HOW EMBARRASSING.
MY OWN BROTHER BUYING ME?
I'D RATHER DIE.
THANK YOU.
MAYBE YOU'RE NOT THAT SELFISH.
- YOU ACTUALLY WENT OUT THERE.
I WAS IMPRESSED
THAT YOU GAVE IT A SHOT.
- EXCUSE ME.
IS THIS YOUR CAR?
- YES. IT'S HIS.
- YOU'RE UNDER ARREST--
- OW! OW!
- FOR THE FORCED ABDUCTION
OF HELEN MARIA DELGADO.
- WHAT'D YOU DO?
- JUST TRYING TO BE
A GOOD GUY.
- ME TOO.
ME TOO.
LET'S GO SEE POP-POP.
[siren wails]
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT"...
MICHAEL GETS A LUCKY BREAK
WHEN HELEN MAKES THE SAME
MISTAKE THAT HE DID.
- FOUR. CUATRO.
- FOUR, STEP FORWARD.
- AND GOB KICKS HIMSELF
FOR A BAD BUSINESS DECISION.
- LOOK, A SEAGULL!
- [munching]
- I NEVER SHOULD'VE
GIVEN UP ANIMATION RIGHTS.