male narrator:
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
narrator: MICHAEL BLUTH WAS
VISITING HIS FATHER IN PRISON,
ANXIOUS TO GET TO THE BOTTOM
OF SOME MYSTERIOUS BOOKKEEPING.
- IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE, DAD.
I MEAN,
WHERE DID THIS MONEY COME FROM?
AND WHY DID IT END UP IN
THE INTERNATIONAL ACCOUNTS FILE?
Narrator:
GEORGE SR. WAS ALSO ANXIOUS--
- DAD!
Narrator:
BUT LESS ABOUT THE BOOKKEEPING.
- THIS GAME
IS NEVER GONNA HAPPEN.
LOOK AT THIS.
HALF OF THESE GUYS
ARE STILL IN THEIR CUFFS.
- I HATE TO BE A BUZZ KILL,
BUT I'M TRYING TO GET YOU
OUT OF HERE.
- YEAH, WELL, I'M TRYING
TO GET US
OUT OF LAST PLACE, MICHAEL.
WE'RE PLAYING RAHWAY NEXT WEEK.
WORD HAS IT THAT
THEY'RE GETTING JOSE CANSECO.
- I'M STARTING TO WONDER
WHY I EVEN BOTHER COMING.
- BLUTH! RIGHT FIELD!
- THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
- YOU WON'T EVEN TALK TO ME!
- I'M CATCHER OR I'M NOTHING!
Narrator:
MICHAEL RETURNED TO WORK,
WHERE HIS ASSISTANT, KITTY,
GREETED HIM WITH
SOME STARTLING NEWS.
- YOUR WIFE'S ON LINE ONE.
Narrator: MICHAEL'S WIFE
HAD BEEN DEAD FOR TWO YEARS.
- MY WHAT?
Narrator:
KITTY REALIZED HER MISTAKE.
- I SAID, YOUR WIFE
IS ON LINE ONE.
Narrator:
BUT NOT IMMEDIATELY.
- OH! OH, GOD.
I'M SORRY.
GEORGE'S WIFE.
YOUR MOTHER.
I'M SO USED TO
BEING GEORGE'S ASSISTANT.
Narrator:
KITTY HAD BEEN GEORGE SR.'s
FIERCELY LOYAL ASSISTANT
FOR YEARS.
AND MICHAEL SUSPECTED
THAT SHE HAD
THE INFORMATION HE NEEDED.
- HEY, KITTY, LISTEN,
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
IF WE HAD ANY DOCUMENTATION
ON THESE INTERNATIONAL ACCOUNTS,
WOULD YOU?
- THAT'S ACTUALLY
NOT ANY OF YOUR BUSINESS.
MY BUSINESS.
THAT'S NOT
ANY OF MY BUSINESS.
- HEY, MOM.
- ARE YOU AWARE
THAT WE'VE BEEN DOWNGRADED
TO BEING JUST
POOL MEMBERS AT THE CLUB NOW?
- YEAH, IT'S A REAL SHAME
WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH THIS FAMILY.
YOU'RE STUCK BY THE POOL,
AND DAD'S GETTING PICKED LAST
FOR SOFTBALL.
- NONETHELESS, MICHAEL,
YOU CAN FREE UP
A LITTLE COMPANY MONEY
TO GET BACK OUR GOLF PRIVILEGES.
- NO, I CAN'T.
MOM, YOU DON'T EVEN PLAY GOLF.
- NO, BUT I USE
THE CLUBHOUSE DINING ROOM--
UNTIL I WAS TURNED AWAY TODAY.
IT'S EMBARRASSING--
TAKE IT BACK!
[woman gasps]
IF I WANTED SOMETHING
YOUR THUMB TOUCHED,
I'D EAT
THE INSIDE OF YOUR EAR!
YOU SHOULD SEE
THE LOOKS I'M GETTING.
FINE,
IF YOU CAN'T FREE UP THE CASH,
HAVE YOUR FATHER
CALL THE CLUB PRESIDENT.
- I'VE GOT NEWS FOR YOU, MOM--
I'M NOT VISITING DAD
IN JAIL ANYMORE.
- [gasps]
- NO, I'VE HAD IT.
I REALLY HAVE.
YOU KNOW, I'M DOWN THERE
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
I'M TRYING TO DO WHAT I CAN TO
GET THIS COMPANY BACK ON TRACK,
AND HE BARELY EVEN
ACKNOWLEDGES ME.
- THAT IS DISGUSTING!
TALK TO YOUR FATHER.
I WILL NOT STAND FOR THIS!
[loud banging]
- [groans]
- GOB!
CAN I, UH...
GET YOU TO STOP DOING THAT?
- I'M JUST SETTING UP
AN OFFICE.
GOTTA WRITE
A STRONGLY WORDED LETTER
TO ONE WARDEN JAMES BUCK.
narrator: IN ORDER TO RESTORE
HIS CAREER AS AN ESCAPE ARTIST,
GOB HAD RECENTLY CHECKED INTO
PRISON AS A PUBLICITY STUNT.
- YOU REALLY THINK YOU CAN
BREAK OUT OF MY PRISON?
- YOU WON'T EVEN KNOW
I WAS HERE.
narrator:
BUT AFTER A SHIV TO HIS SIDE,
GOB WAS RUSHED
TO A LOCAL HOSPITAL,
THUS FULFILLING, IN GOB'S MIND,
HIS CONTRACT WITH THE PUBLIC.
- [singing]
TA-DAH.
narrator:
AND YET THE WARDEN HAD REFUSED
TO ACKNOWLEDGE
THE LEGITIMACY OF THE ESCAPE.
- SO I AM GOING AFTER THIS GUY
WITH EVERYTHING I'VE GOT...
ART.
NOW WE ARE WRITING
A LETTER.
- GOB?
WELL, I WISH I WOULD'VE KNOWN
YOU WERE COMING.
I AM A MESS.
- DON'T KNOW IF A CALL FROM ME
WOULD'VE CHANGED THAT.
- [snickers]
DO YOU LIKE MY OUTFIT?
- NOT AS MUCH AS
I LIKE WHAT'S UNDERNEATH IT.
- GOB!
- NO, I NEED YOUR CHAIR.
GET UP.
I'VE GOT A LETTER TO WRITE.
- WHOO!
YOU'RE ALL BUSINESS.
JUST LIKE YOUR DAD.
- [mutters]
MY GOD, SHE'S REPULSIVE.
narrator:
MICHAEL REALIZED
THAT KITTY'S
OBVIOUS ATTRACTION TO GOB
COULD PERHAPS BE
OF USE TO HIM.
- GOB, HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
A TOUCH LAMP?
- YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO NEEDS THERAPY!
Narrator:
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
PREPARED FOR THEIR FIRST
SESSION WITH A THERAPIST.
- YES, TOBIAS,
I WANT THE MARRIAGE TO WORK.
I JUST DON'T KNOW
IF THERAPY IS THE ANSWER.
- OH, RIGHT, BECAUSE YOU
DIDN'T RESPECT MY OLD CAREER,
AND YOU CERTAINLY
DON'T RESPECT MY NEW ONE!
- YOU DON'T HAVE
A NEW ONE!
Narrator:
THINGS HAD BEEN TENSE
SINCE TOBIAS
LEFT HIS PSYCHIATRY PRACTICE
TO PURSUE AN ACTING CAREER.
- I HAVE NEEDS, YOU KNOW.
- AND HOW AM I NOT
ADDRESSING YOUR NEEDS?
- HOW CAN YOU EVEN ASK THAT?
WHAT IS THIS?
- OH! GO RIGHT TO THAT!
GOOD. GO RIGHT THERE.
REAL MATURE. REALLY GREAT.
OKAY, KIDS...
MOMMY AND DADDY
ARE GOING OUT FOR ICE CREAM.
- CAN WE COME?
- SORRY.
IT'S NOT FOR KIDS.
[door opens, closes]
- WELL, NOW WE HAVE
TO FOLLOW THEM.
- YEAH.
WHAT?
- OKAY, SO,
WHY ARE WE DOING THIS?
- 'CAUSE IT'S OBVIOUS
THEY'RE LYING.
COME ON, DRIVE!
- WELL, WHAT IF THEY SEE US?
- HOW ARE THEY GONNA SEE US?
- WELL, IT SAYS "BLUTH COMPANY"
RIGHT ON THE SIDE.
PLUS, IT'S A STAIRWAY.
THAT'S GONNA CATCH THE EYE.
Narrator:
THE AIRPORT STAIRWAY VEHICLE
WAS THE LAST VESTIGE
OF THE BLUTHS' FORMER WEALTH.
ALSO, THAT HOUSE OF PIES
WENT OUT OF BUSINESS.
- YOU ARE SCARED.
I KNEW IT.
NO, I'M NOT SCARED.
IT'S JUST THAT...
I HAVE PLANS LATER.
I-I'M VISITING POP-POP.
- YOU VISIT POP-POP?
Narrator:
IN FACT, HE'D BEEN TERRIFIED
OF THE VERY NOTION OF PRISON
SINCE, AS A YOUNG BOY,
HE ACCIDENTALLY WATCHED
HBO's "OZ",
MISTAKING IT FOR THE CLASSIC
JUDY GARLAND MUSICAL.
- I'M AN INNOCENT MAN!
- EAT IT, BITCH!
- LOTS OF TIMES.
- WHAT'S IT LIKE?
- HEY, YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU SHOULD DO?
YOU SHOULD GO GET
YOUR MOM'S DATE BOOK.
- OH, YEAH.
SHE MUST HAVE WRITTEN DOWN
WHERE THEY'RE GOING.
OH, HEY, I STILL WANNA
HEAR ABOUT PRISON, OKAY?
- WELL, IF YOU CAN HANDLE IT.
[door closes]
Narrator: MICHAEL ARRIVED HOME
IN A GOOD MOOD.
WITH GOB GETTING
THE INFORMATION FROM KITTY,
HE WOULD NO LONGER
HAVE TO VISIT PRISON
AND DEAL WITH HIS FATHER.
- HEY, BUDDY!
CAME HOME EARLY.
WANNA DO SOMETHIN'?
ANYTHING. ANYTHING AT ALL.
- I WANNA VISIT POP-POP
IN PRISON.
Narrator:
BACK AT THE OFFICE,
GOB WAS MAKING PROGRESS
WITH MICHAEL'S ASSISTANT.
- HERE'S WHERE WE KEEP
ALL OF OUR...
HEAVYWEIGHT PAPER.
- BET YOU CAN SHOW ME
WHERE A LOT OF THINGS ARE.
- WHAT KIND OF THINGS
ARE YOU...
LOOKING FOR?
- WHAT, UH--
WHAT ARE YOU HIDING?
- NOTHING YOU CAN'T FIND.
- WAIT A SECOND.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
TAKE OFF YOUR GLASSES.
OH.
WAIT, WAIT.
LET DOWN YOUR HAIR.
[man singing]
YEAH, BABY
NO. GLASSES ON.
HAIR BACK UP.
LET'S JUST GET THAT HAIR
RIGHT BACK UP.
- DO YOU WANT ME TO
TURN ALL THE LIGHTS OFF?
WHAT ABOUT THAT?
- YES, YES, PLEASE.
- HOW'S THAT?
IS THAT BETTER?
- IT JUST SEEMS
LIKE THERE'S STILL LIGHT
COMING IN
FROM UNDER THE DOOR.
Narrator:
AND LINDSAY AND TOBIAS WERE,
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
ADDRESSING
THEIR MARITAL PROBLEMS.
- IT'S LIKE WE'RE
FACE TO FACE NOW,
LIKE WE'RE REALLY
SEEING THIS MARRIAGE AND...
I'M AFRAID IT'S A LIE.
[slow, deliberate applause]
- BRAVO.
SEE, IF I GAVE A PERFORMANCE
THAT GOOD,
I'D HAVE MY OWN
"ALIAS" TYPE SHOW.
- STOP IT.
I AM SO SICK OF HEARING
ABOUT ACTING, ACTING, ACTING!
- OKAY, OKAY, LOOK.
MAYBE WE NEED A NEW APPROACH.
UM...LET'S TRY
SOME ROLE PLAYING.
- YES! ALL RIGHT.
- [sighs]
Narrator: MICHAEL HEADED BACK
TO THE PRISON,
DESPITE HIS EARLIER VOW
NEVER TO RETURN.
- WELL, YOU ALWAYS SAY
FAMILY FIRST.
I SHOULD SEE MY GRANDPA, RIGHT?
- NOW, LISTEN.
I'M NOT STOPPING YOU,
BUT JUST, AFTER THIS
I'M NOT GOING BACK OUT THERE.
- WHY?
IS IT SCARY?
- SCARY? NO.
NO.
IT'S THE OPPOSITE OF SCARY.
IT'S LIKE A CARNIVAL.
WITHOUT THE HALF-PERSON
ON THE SKATEBOARD
THAT GRABBED YOUR KNEE
TO STEADY HIMSELF.
IT'S LIKE A COUNTRY CLUB.
ALL THE GUY DOES
IS EAT ICE CREAM
AND PLAY SOFTBALL ALL DAY.
Narrator: IN FACT,
GEORGE SR.'s SOFTBALL GAME
HAD TAKEN MOST OF THE DAY.
IT WAS THE 14th INNING,
AND TENSIONS
WERE RUNNING A LITTLE HIGH.
- I'LL GIVE YOU
A THOUSAND BUCKS,
YOU CALL THE NEXT ONE A STRIKE.
MY KNEES ARE KILLING ME.
NO BATTER!
NO BATTER HERE!
NO BATTER.
- STRIKE THREE!
- STRIKE THREE, MY ASS!
[bat pounds umpire]
- OHH!
- DOWN IN THE YARD! GET DOWN!
- [gunshots]
- NO BATTER.
NO--NO BATTER.
NO--SHH.
- OKAY, THERE HE IS.
NOW GO ON IN THERE
AND SURPRISE HIM.
I'M GONNA GET US
A FEW ICE CREAM SANDWICHES.
GO ON. GO ON.
- HEY, POP-POP.
HOW'S PRISON?
- I'M GONNA DIE IN HERE.
- WHAT?
- THEY'RE GONNA KILL GRANDPA.
AH, I GOTTA--
I GOTTA GET OUTTA HERE.
I'M AN INNOCENT MAN.
YOU GOTTA HELP POP-POP
GET OUTTA HERE.
GIVE ME YOUR HAIR.
- MY HAIR?
- GIVE ME YOUR HAIR!
GIVE POP-POP YOUR HAIR!
- NO TOUCHING!
NO TOUCHING! NO TOUCHING!
- GIVE ME THE HAIR!
- ONE OF THESE GOT SMOOSHED,
BUT DON'T LET THAT
RUIN PRISON FOR YOU.
- NO BATTER.
[chuckles]
NO BATTER. NO BATTER.
- COME ON, BABY!
THROW THE BALL!
- I'M SURE YOUR GRANDFATHER
WAS JUST KIDDING AROUND.
YOU KNOW THAT'S
HIS SENSE OF HUMOR.
- I KNOW, I KNOW.
YEAH.
I DON'T--
I DON'T TOTALLY GET
THE HAIR JOKE,
BUT I'M FINE, DAD.
- ARE YOU SURE?
I AM GONNA HEAD BACK IN,
THOUGH, OKAY?
I'M GONNA SEE IF POP-POP'S
GOT ANY MORE ZINGERS.
- [laughs]
- WHY DON'T YOU JUST STAY OUT
HERE AND RELAX, PAL, OKAY?
WATCH THE SOFTBALL GAME.
- OKAY.
- I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[alarm buzzer buzzes]
- HEY, STOP! STOP!
- [footsteps pounding]
- [gunshots]
- DAD?
- JUST DON'T
LIKE PRISON ANYMORE.
- WELL, THAT'S WHY I'M TRYING
TO GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
- I DON'T KNOW,
MAYBE I'VE BEEN IN DENIAL,
BUT THIS PLACE
IS BREAKING ME, MIKEY,
AND I'M ALONE HERE,
BUT FOR YOU.
- COME ON.
YOU GOT ME, YOU GOT MOM.
- [chuckles]
YOUR MOTHER'S NEVER
SHOWN HER FACE.
- WHOA.
SHE'S NEVER BEEN HERE?
YOU SHOULD'VE HEARD
THE GRIEF SHE GAVE ME
WHEN I SAID
I'D NEVER SHOW UP AGAIN.
- YOU SAID--YOU SAID WHAT?
[cuffs clang on bars]
- DAD, COME ON,
YOU DON'T NEED ME.
YOU'RE PLAYING SOFTBALL
ALL THE TIME.
- I DO NEED YOU, MICHAEL!
NO MORE SOFTBALL.
- THIS IS NUTS, YOU KNOW.
I MEAN, YOU'RE HER HUSBAND.
THE LEAST SHE COULD DO IS
COME OUT AND VISIT YOU, RIGHT?
- GOD, YOU KNOW YOUR MOM.
THIS ISN'T HER CROWD.
SHE'S VERY EASILY THREATENED.
YOU REMEMBER THE CARJACKER?
[aerosol hissing]
- AAAH!
- WELL, SHE'S CERTAINLY
TOUGHENED UP SINCE THEN.
YOU KNOW, SHE'S EATING LUNCH
BY THE POOL NOW.
- WELL, THERE'S A BIG DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN THE COUNTRY CLUB POOL
AND THE CONJUGAL TRAILER.
- THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT
WHEN I SAID "VISIT."
- YOU KNOW, IT'S TOO BAD,
BECAUSE I REALLY MISS
THAT PERSONAL CONTACT.
IT WAS THE ONE THING THAT
CALMED ME WHEN I GOT STRESSED.
IT JUST FELT...HUMANIZING.
Narrator:
MICHAEL, FOR THE FIRST TIME,
SAW HIS FATHER
AS A VULNERABLE HUMAN BEING.
- [whimpers]
DADDY HORNY, MICHAEL.
I JUST HAVEN'T HAD SEX
IN A MONTH.
- YOU KNOW, YOU'VE BEEN HERE
TWO MONTHS.
- IT'S HARD TO GAUGE TIME.
- YEAH, I'LL BET.
- [clears throat]
[door closes]
- HEY, MOM.
I WENT TO VISIT DAD TODAY.
QUICK QUESTION.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE YOU
TO GET OUT THERE?
- OH, I'VE NEVER BEEN.
- THEN WHY DOES HE TELL ME
THAT YOU'VE NEVER BEEN?
- [belches]
OOH. SORRY, MICHAEL.
POOL FOOD.
MY SYSTEM'S
NOT USED TO CURLY FRIES.
- HOW CAN YOU
IGNORE THAT MAN?
YOU KNOW, HE'S HAVING
A HARD TIME IN THERE.
HE'S LONELY.
- THAT'S WHAT
HIS CHILDREN ARE FOR.
- YEAH, WELL, YOU KNOW...
THERE ARE
CERTAIN THINGS THAT
HE CAN'T GET
FROM HIS CHILDREN.
- IF YOU'RE GOING TO SAY
"PRIDE," MICHAEL, YOU'RE WRONG.
HE IS PROUD OF HIS CHILDREN.
- WASN'T GONNA SAY PRIDE,
MOM.
UH, LISTEN,
I-I-I THINK THAT, UM--
I THINK THAT YOU SHOULD--
OH, I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M GONNA SAY THIS.
I THINK THAT YOU SHOULD...
VISIT HIM...
IN AN...INTIMATE,
MARITAL...TRAILER.
- ARE YOU MAD?
- YOU THINK I'M COMFORTABLE
ASKING YOU TO DO THIS?
I MEAN, HE NEEDS YOU, MOM.
- DID HE SAY THAT?
DID HE SAY
THAT HE MISSES ME?
DOES HE NEED
HIS WIFE'S EMBRACE?
- [whimpers]
DADDY HORNY, MICHAEL.
- HE SAID
SOME WONDERFUL THINGS.
- YOU REALLY WANT THIS FOR HIM,
DON'T YOU?
- I DO.
- "GOLF MEMBERSHIP"
WANT IT?
Narrator:
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
WERE GETTING TO THE HEART
OF EACH OTHER'S VULNERABILITIES
WITH A ROLE-REVERSAL EXERCISE.
- BECAUSE I'M A WOMAN!
- GOOD.
- WITH A WOMAN'S NEEDS.
- LOUDER.
- AND A WOMAN'S URGES!
AND THESE, TOBIAS.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU LOOKED AT THESE?
- YEAH, OKAY.
HOW LONG IS THIS SESSION?
- OKAY, WELL, SEE, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE.
SHE'S BREAKING IN AND OUT
OF CHARACTER
AND MAKING IT DIFFICULT--
- 'CAUSE I DON'T WANNA
BE IN A CHARACTER.
- OKAY, LET ME STOP YOU GUYS.
ALL RIGHT?
PLEASE. LET ME GET IN HERE.
- THANK YOU.
[mutters] GOD.
- [clears throat]
- YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
A REAL WIFE TO ME, LINDSAY.
- THAT'S NOT TRUE!
AND YOU KNOW IT!
- A MAN IS LOOKING BACK AT YOU.
A MAN WITH DREAMS
AND ASPIRATIONS!
Narrator: MEANWHILE,
MAEBY FOUND AN ADDRESS
IN HER
MOTHER'S APPOINTMENT BOOK...
AND WAS GETTING CLOSER
TO LEARNING WHAT HER PARENTS
WERE UP TO.
- RIGHT!
IF I'M NO SCHWIMMER,
YOU'RE NO JENNIFER ANISTON!
- [sobbing] MAYBE I'M NOT EVEN
LISA KUDROW.
- I-I HAVE DREAMS, LINDSAY.
DREAMS, LINDSAY.
- WELL, THEN, TOBIAS...
FOLLOW THOSE DREAMS.
MAKE THOSE DREAMS HAPPEN.
- YES. I WILL.
- AND SCENE!
- [sighs]
WOW!
- OKAY.
I'M SORRY
I STEPPED ON YOUR LINE.
- NO, NOT AT ALL.
UH, LINDSAY, I MEAN,
DID THAT ANSWER
SOME QUESTIONS FOR YOU?
- YEAH, YEAH,
I THINK IT DID, YEAH
NOW THERE ARE TWO MEN
I WANNA LEAVE.
Narrator:
MICHAEL ARRIVED HOME,
HAPPY TO HAVE A BROTHER
TO SHARE HIS RECENT BURDEN WITH.
- GREAT NEWS.
- OH, GOOD.
I COULD USE IT, BUDDY.
I JUST CAME FROM CONVINCING MOM
TO HAVE SEX WITH DAD.
- GOD! WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
THAT IS DISGUSTING!
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
- OH, I'M SORRY.
BUT JUST THE THOUGHT
OF MOM AND DAD TOGETHER--
I HAVE A SENSE OF PROPRIETY.
ALL RIGHT?
- FINE.
WHAT'S YOUR GREAT NEWS?
- I [bleep] KITTY.
- OH, GOB, I JUST WANTED YOU
TO GET THE INFORMATION.
- OH, I GOT THE INFORMATION.
- YOU DID, HUH?
ABOUT
THE INTERNATIONAL ACCOUNTS?
- OH, I SEE WHAT
YOU'RE GETTING AT.
NO, I DIDN'T GET
ANY INFORMATION.
- THAT'S GREAT.
GOOD, GOOD, GOOD, GOB.
WELL, YOU JUST
LOST THE TOUCH LAMP.
- WHAT? NO!
- YEAH, THE DEAL'S OFF!
FORGET IT.
I'M GONNA USE THE TOUCH LAMP
TO SET THE MOOD
IN THE CONJUGAL
TRAILER WHEN DAD'S NAILING MOM!
- NO! DON'T--
MICHAEL!
YOU ARE FILTHY!
Narrator:
THE TWO COUSINS REUNITED,
EACH A LITTLE SHAKEN
BY WHAT THEY HAD PRETENDED
TO BE FEARLESS ABOUT.
- SO YOU THINK
THEY'LL GET DIVORCED?
- I DON'T CARE, AND I'M NOT
SAYING "I DON'T CARE"
LIKE KIDS WHO SAY THEY DON'T
CARE WHEN THEY REALLY DO CARE,
'CAUSE I REALLY DON'T CARE.
- RIGHT. I KNOW.
WHO CARES, RIGHT?
- I MEAN, I CARE.
-  HOW COULD YOU NOT?
- YOU KNOW, OUR FAMILY'S
REALLY MESSED UP.
- I KNOW.
WE'RE LIKE THE ONLY NORMAL ONES.
- AT LEAST WE GOT
EACH OTHER. RIGHT?
- GEORGE MICHAEL?
- SORRY.
[chuckles]
SOMETIMES I JUST DON'T KNOW
IF IT'S GONNA BE
A LONG HUG OR A SHORT HUG
OR, LIKE, A MIDDLE-MEDIUM HUG.
IT'S HARD TO TELL
SOMETIMES.
YEAH, BUT, THAT WAS A GOOD HUG.
THAT'S PLENTY FOR NOW.
I DON'T CARE.
HUG'S GOTTA END SOMETIME,
OBVIOUSLY.
Narrator: SOON, MICHAEL
WAS DRIVING LUCILLE TO PRISON,
AND SHE SEEMED TO BE
LOOKING FORWARD TO IT.
- WHERE ARE WE GOING AFTER?
- HEY, DAD.
- MICHAEL!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- YOU NEEDED MY HELP,
AND I KNOW IT WAS HARD
FOR YOU TO ASK,
SO I TOOK IT UPON MYSELF
TO BRING HER.
- THAT DOESN'T MAKE YOU
UNCOMFORTABLE?
- WELL, YEAH, THE DRIVE
WAS A LITTLE AWKWARD.
- NOT EVERY SON WOULD DO THIS
FOR HIS FATHER.
THANK YOU FOR THIS.
- HELLO, GEORGE.
- WHAT THE HELL'S
YOUR MOTHER DOING IN HERE?
- WHO WERE YOU EXPECTING?
- OH, I'VE DONE A BAD THING.
I'VE DONE
A TERRIBLE THING.
- THERE'S SOMEONE ELSE
IN THAT TRAILER, ISN'T THERE?
- I'VE DONE A REPULSIVE THING.
- WAIT--WHOA.
IT'S KITTY?
- SHH!
- HOW LONG?
WHEN DID THIS START?
- OH, COME ON! COME ON!
- THIS IS THE FIRST TIME.
EVERY FRIDAY
FOR THE LAST EIGHT YEARS.
- [sighs]
- MICHAEL, DADDY--
- HORNY. I GOT THAT.
- OH, COME ON.
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS IS EASY.
THIS IS AN EASY ONE.
NOW, I'LL GO IN THERE
WITH KITTY, I'LL DO MY THING,
AND TH-TH-THEN
I'LL GO AND SEE YOUR MOTH--
THIS IS A HARD ONE.
- SHE'S YOUR SECRETARY.
- SEE, YOU'RE RIGHT.
FAMILY FIRST.
TAKE CARE OF KITTY.
MICHAEL.
I NEED YOU NOW.
- "INTERNATIONAL ACCOUNTS"
NEED ME?
Narrator:
AND SO AN AGREEMENT WAS MADE.
GEORGE SR.
WOULD REVEAL THE TRUTH,
AND MICHAEL WOULD MAKE SURE
KITTY DIDN'T COME OUT
OF THE TRAILER.
[phone rings]
- YEAH?
- HEY, GOB, WHERE ARE YOU?
I NEED YOU TO COME
TO THE PRISON.
- I'M AT THE PRISON.
- YOU'RE HERE?
- I'M DELIVERING
THIS STRONGLY WORDED LETTER
I WROTE...
LIT BY NOTHING
BUT NATURAL LIGHT.
- WELL, HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
THAT TOUCH LAMP
AND THE OFFICE
AND--WHAT THE HELL--
FULL USE OF THE SECRETARY?
- THANK YOU FOR DOING THIS.
IT MEANS A--
IT MEANS A LOT.
I, UH--OKAY,
I'LL GET DOWN ON THE COUCH.
- I'M NOT GOING TO HAVE SEX
WITH YOU, GEORGE.
I CAME TO TELL YOU
HOW MUCH I HATE YOU FOR
WHAT YOU'VE DONE TO THIS FAMILY.
- YOU'RE ANGRY.
- YOU'VE RUINED US.
- I'VE RUINED US?
YOU GOT A LOT OF NERVE, HONEY.
THE MILLIONS YOU PISSED AWAY
ON CLOTHING AND JEWELRY
AND THE SPA TREATMENTS--
- YES, TO KEEP YOU INTERESTED
IN THE ONLY THING
YOU EVER APPRECIATED--
MY BODY.
- CAN I HELP IT
IF YOU'VE GOT A FANTASTIC BODY?
- AND YOU'RE AS POWERFUL
AS A BEAR.
MY HUSBAND THE BEAR.
- THIS BEAR NEEDS
SOME HONEY, WIFE.
- OH, GOD, I MISSED YOU!
[gasps, groans]
Narrator:
GOB, MEANWHILE,
STALLED TO KEEP KITTY
IN THE OTHER TRAILER.
- GLASSES OFF.
GLASSES ON.
HAIR UP.
GLASSES OFF.
DOWN, ON.
HAVE WE DONE UP, OFF?
- OH, GOB,
THIS IS SO WRONG.
- AND BRIGHT.
WRONG A-AND BRIGHT.
THIS--
THAT'S BET--BRIGHTER!
GOD! DAMN.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA--I'M JUST GONNA
WASH UP REAL QUICK.
- UH, I THINK
I'M GONNA GO WITH--
WITH DOWN AND OFF.
Narrator:
GOB HAD TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
BUT AS HE HEADED TO HIS CAR,
HE RAN INTO THE WARDEN,
WHO HAD JUST READ
HIS STRONGLY WORDED LETTER.
- WELL, IF IT ISN'T
"SINCERELY YOURS."
Narrator:
AND SO GOB WAS DETAINED
AGAINST THE WINDOW
OF THE TRAILER
HIS PARENTS
WERE BECOMING INTIMATE IN.
[moaning]
- [sobbing]
OH, GOD, MOMMY!
WHAT DID YOU DO?
- HEY, BUDDY.
- HEY, WHERE WERE YOU?
I HAD TO HELP OUT
YOUR GRANDFATHER,
AND THEN I HAD TO VOW
THAT I WOULD NEVER HELP
YOUR GRANDFATHER AGAIN.
PRETTY MUCH
A NORMAL DAY FOR ME.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
- I'M FINE, I GUESS.
IT'S JUST--
YOU KNOW, YOU THINK OF PRISON
AS THIS PLACE
FULL OF GUILTY PEOPLE
AND IT DOESN'T
BOTHER YOU THAT MUCH.
BUT IF POP-POP COULD BE THERE,
THEN ANYBODY COULD BE THERE.
AND I DON'T WANNA
GO TO PRISON, DAD.
I DON'T THINK I COULD TAKE IT.
I MEAN, I KNOW I ACT TOUGH,
BUT I--
- IS THIS
WHAT YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT?
'CAUSE, YOU KNOW, I GOT NEWS--
HE'S, UH--
HE'S GUILTY.
- HE IS?
- OH, YEAH.
INCREDIBLY GUILTY.
- [exhales]
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
TOBIAS TALKS LINDSAY
INTO ANOTHER SESSION.
- AND I'VE DECIDED THAT...
[sighs]
I WANT TO BECOME
AN ACTOR TOO.
[laughs]
narrator: AND GEORGE SR.
MAKES GOOD ON HIS PROMISE
TO COME CLEAN
ON THE INTERNATIONAL ACCOUNTS.
- THERE'S A GOOD CHANCE THAT I--
THAT I MAY HAVE COMMITTED SOME,
UM, LIGHT...
TREASON.
- [groans]