narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL BLUTH
HAD CALLED A MEETING...
WITH THE FAMILY'S
LONGTIME ATTORNEY...
TO DISCUSS
HIS FATHER'S INCARCERATION.
- I AM SO SORRY.
IT WAS A CLIENT. OKAY.
- BUT HE WAS FINDING IT
DIFFICULT TO GET ANY ANSWERS.
- HOW LONG
WAS I ON THE PHONE?
- TWENTY-FIVE MINUTES.
- WITH THE CELL PHONE CHARGES,
I'M GONNA ROUND IT OUT
TO ABOUT AN HOUR...
'CAUSE IT'S EASIER TO BILL--
ALL RIGHT.
ANYTHING ELSE TO GO OVER?
- WE'VE GOT
EVERYTHING ELSE TO GO OVER.
WE HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING
TO GET MY DAD OUT OF JAIL.
- OKAY. FIRST OF ALL-- WHAT ARE
YOU DOING? PILATES?
BECAUSE NO 40-YEAR-OLD WOMAN
SHOULD LOOK LIKE THAT.
- WELL, NO 40-YEAR-OLD WOMAN
DOES LOOK LIKE THAT.
narrator: HE WAS, HOWEVER,
GETTING ALONG WITH HIS SISTER,
WHICH WAS UNWELCOME NEWS
TO THEIR MOTHER,
WHO FEARED THIS UNITY
MIGHT BE USED AGAINST HER.
- I DO HAVE SOME BIG NEWS.
IT'S GOING TO COST YOU
A LITTLE MONEY--
20,000,
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THE COURTS HAVE AGREED TO LET
YOUR FATHER OUT OF PRISON.
- THIS IS A LAWYER!
- HE'S A MASTER!
- FOR THE ENTIRE AFTERNOON.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN "AFTERNOON"?
WHAT AFTERNOON?
- THE DAY BEFORE CHRISTMAS,
IN TIME FOR THE
LIVING CLASSICS PAGEANT,
BECAUSE I KNOW HOW IMPORTANT
THAT IS TO ALL OF YOU.
narrator:
THE LIVING CLASSICS PAGEANT,
AN ORANGE COUNTY TRADITION,
CONSISTS OF LIVE REPRESENTATIONS
OF CLASSIC WORKS OF ART.
THE BLUTH FAMILY HAS
PARTICIPATED
NOT ONLY AS A PATRON,
BUT AS AN INTEGRAL PART
OF ITS MOST POPULAR EXHIBIT,
MICHELANGELO'S
THE CREATION OF ADAM.
- I DON'T REALLY WANT
TO BE ADAM THIS YEAR.
- WELL, IF YOU WANT TO PLAY EVE,
YOU GOT TO GET IN LINE...
BEHIND, WHAT,
ABOUT FIVE HOMOS.
THAT WAS WRONG.
I'M--I'M SO SORRY.
IT'S JUST THAT I HAVE ONE
DOWN AT THE OFFICE NOW,
AND, I MEAN,
IT IS EVERY DAY.
- I WOULD BE HAPPY TO PLAY ADAM.
I'D PREFER A SPEAKING PART--
- PLEASE DON'T SPEAK FOR
THE REST OF THE MEETING.
- [chuckles]
ZING!
- NO, NO, SERIOUSLY.
I DON'T WANT TO PLAY ADAM.
- BUSTER, EVERY YEAR WE GO
THROUGH THIS SONG AND DANCE,
AND EVERY YEAR YOU SAY,
"THANK YOU, MAMA,
FOR MAKING ME PLAY ADAM."
YOU'RE DOING IT.
narrator:
THIS CONCERNED BUSTER...
AS HE'D BEEN SECRETLY DATING
HIS MOTHER'S BEST FRIEND...
AND CHIEF SOCIAL RIVAL,
LUCILLE AUSTERO.
- CAN'T WE JUST STAY HERE
AND PLAY POKER AGAIN?
YOU CAN BET YOUR VERTIGO
MEDICINE
AGAINST MY ANXIETY PILLS.
- NO. BUSTER, FOR GOD'S SAKE,
THERE IS MUSIC TO HEAR,
PLACES TO GO,
ENVY TO STIR.
LOOK, I'M TIRED OF KEEPING
OUR LOVE A SECRET.
WE ARE GOING OUT,
AND THAT IS THAT!
- OH.
- OH, BUSTER. OKAY, I'M OKAY.
I'M OKAY.
- OKAY. I'M GONNA
GET OUT OF YOUR HAIR.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THIS MONEY
LATER IN THE WEEK.
- EXCUSE ME.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO PAY
$20,000
TO GET MY DAD OUT
FOR ONE DAY.
- NO. IT'S A BOND.
IT'S ALL REFUNDABLE,
UNLIKE MY TIME.
- IT'S BEEN A COMPLETE WASTE
OF TWO HOURS, OKAY?
WE'RE JUST NOT GOING TO DO IT,
AND THAT'S THAT.
ARE YOU WRITING TWO HOURS?
- NO, I'M TAKING NOTES
ON THE CASE.
- LET ME JUST SEE
WHAT YOU JUST WROTE.
- YOU'RE SCARING ME.
JUST LEAVE IT ALONE!
IT IS A GIFT FROM A CLIENT!
[door slams]
- BARRY'S VERY GOOD.
- HE'S AN IDIOT.
- EXACTLY. WE'RE NOT TRYING
TO GET DAD OUT FOR A NIGHT.
WE'RE TRYING
TO GET HIM OUT FOR GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA GET A NEW LAWYER.
I ACTUALLY KNOW OF ONE
WHO'S AVAILABLE.
HIS NAME'S WAYNE JARVIS.
HE'S A TOP GUY.
narrator: WAYNE JARVIS
HAD BECOME FAMOUS...
AFTER AN EMPLOYMENT
DISCRIMINATION SUIT...
AGAINST THE FAMILY'S
CURRENT ATTORNEY,
BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
- IT'LL BE A LONG TIME
BEFORE BARRY ZUCKERKORN
CALLS ANYONE A HOMO AGAIN.
- YOU KNOW, I AM REALLY HAPPY
THAT YOU TWO ARE IN AGREEMENT,
BUT WE'RE NOT
GETTING RID OF BARRY.
HE'S LIKE FAMILY,
AND YOU CAN'T FIRE FAMILY.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
HEY, MAEBY.
- MAEBY,
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
- YOU LEFT ME AT HOME.
YOU DO REMEMBER YOU HAVE
A DAUGHTER, RIGHT?
- UH, YES,
OF COURSE WE REMEMBER,
AND WE WERE WORRIED SICK,
YOUNG LADY.
SHE'S FINE.
OUR DAUGHTER'S ALL RIGHT,
EVERYBODY, SO--
YOU SAID YOU DIDN'T
WANT HER TO COME.
- I DIDN'T WANT YOU TO COME.
- OH, THAT MAKES MORE SENSE.
- NOW SHE'S GOING TO THINK
WE'RE TOTALLY SELF-INVOLVED.
- I CAN FIX THIS.
BUSTER'S PROBABLY
STILL IN THE LOBBY.
LET ME GO SEE IF I CAN'T GET HIM
TO GIVE ME THE PART OF ADAM.
- AND I'LL SEE IF I CAN
GET SOME MONEY FROM MY MOM.
- LUPE!
THERE ARE SOME JUICE GLASSES
ON THE SOFA TABLE.
- MAMA, I'LL HELP YOU CLEAN UP.
THERE ARE SOME SALAD PLATES
ON THE PIANO.
WOW.
WHAT A PARTY.
YOU MAKE IT SEEM
SO EFFORTLESS.
- WHAT DO YOU NEED MONEY FOR?
A DIVORCE?
- NO, MOM. TOBIAS AND I
ARE DOING FINE, THANK YOU.
IT'S MY CREDIT CARD DEBT.
- FORGET IT.
- FINE. I'LL ASK MICHAEL.
HE'LL GIVE IT TO ME.
- MAYBE IF YOU GET HIM DRUNK.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
HE'LL GIVE MONEY...
TO SOMEONE HE CALLS
A "STAY-IN-BED MOM."
- HE SAID THAT ABOUT ME?
- I THOUGHT IT WAS HARSH.
BUT, YOU KNOW, HE THINKS
YOU'RE COMPLETELY
IRRESPONSIBLE.
A STAY-IN-BED MOM.
PROBABLY BECAUSE YOU DON'T WORK
AND YOU'RE LAZY.
HIS WORDS.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE HIM.
- I KNOW!
JUST WHEN YOU WERE
GETTING ALONG SO WELL.
- THEY'VE GOT TO BE
KIDDING ME.
narrator: MICHAEL'S BROTHER GOB,
MEANWHILE,
HAD MISSED THE MEETING
THAT MORNING
AFTER BEING DELAYED BY HIS
GIRLFRIEND MARTA.
- TE QUIERO!
- ENGLISH, PLEASE.
- I LOVE YOU.
- GREAT.
NOW I'M LATE.
narrator: AND WHILE GOB TOOK
HIS GIRLFRIEND FOR GRANTED,
MICHAEL WAS LEARNING SPANISH
TO GET CLOSER TO HER.
- THAT IS NOT SOMETHING
I CAN BRING TO MY BOSS.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
THE ONE TAPE HE COULD FIND
WAS OF LITTLE USE TO HIM.
- ARE YOU GOING
TO THE COMPLIMENTARY BREAKFAST?
- [speaking Spanish]
THAT'LL GET HER HOT.
- WELL, IF IT ISN'T THE BOY
WHO LIVES UNDER THE STAIRS.
- HEY, GOB.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
LEARNING SPANISH?
- NOPE. IT'S, UH--IT'S SOMETHING
FOR WORK, SO, YES, UH, YEAH.
narrator: MEANWHILE, BUSTER WAS
TRYING TO GET GEORGE MICHAEL..
TO TAKE HIS PLACE AS ADAM.
- I DON'T KNOW,
UNCLE BUSTER.
- WELL, YOU DON'T HAVE
THE "FRONTSPIECE" YET.
- "FRONTSPIECE"?
- LOOK, I DON'T WANT TO GO
THROUGH
A WHOLE SONG AND DANCE WITH YOU.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE IT.
YOU JUST CAN'T DO ANYTHING THAT
VIOLATES THE ORIGINAL PAINTING,
LIKE GIGGLING OR ITCHING.
THEY DO ALLOW
SOME NERVOUS CRYING,
BUT YOU CAN TELL
THEY DON'T LIKE IT.
narrator: AND MAEBY
WAS TEACHING HER PARENTS
A LESSON FOR FORGETTING HER--
- WHO KNOWS
HOW LONG I'LL BE GONE?
narrator: WHEN SHE SPOTTED
GEORGE MICHAEL.
- NICE PECS.
GOT A KICKIN' BOD.
narrator: THUS, GEORGE MICHAEL
FOUND A COMPELLING REASON
TO KEEP THE MUSCLE SUIT ON.
[ringing]
- LAW OFFICES
OF BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
- YEAH, IT'S MICHAEL BLUTH FOR
BARRY.
- [whispers]
I'M NOT HERE.
- BARRY'S NOT HERE.
CAN I GIVE HER A MESSAGE?
- TELL HER SHE NEEDS TO WHISPER
A LITTLE SOFTER NEXT TIME,
AND I'M NOT PAYING
FOR THIS PHONE CALL.
- I AM NOT A GIRL,
YOU BOW-TIED--
- GO ON. CALL ME SOMETHING.
I'M REDOING MY KITCHEN.
- THAT'S IT. I'VE HAD IT
WITH THIS JERK BARRY.
I'M GOING TO MAKE
MOM SIT DOWN WITH WAYNE
WHETHER SHE LIKES IT OR NOT.
- YOU'RE THE JERK.
- DID I JUST WAKE YOU UP?
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU WERE HOME.
- NO, MICHAEL,
I DON'T JUST SLEEP ALL DAY.
narrator: ACTUALLY, LINDSAY
WAS SO UPSET AT MICHAEL...
THAT SHE TRIED MEDITATING
TO CALM HERSELF,
BUT ENDED UP TAKING
A TWO-HOUR ANGRY NAP.
- YEAH, THIS SUITCASE
SHOULD BE BIG ENOUGH.
- WHERE IS ALL THIS COMING FROM?
I THOUGHT WE WERE GETTING ALONG.
- YEAH, SO DID I.
AND NOW I HEAR YOU'RE
TELLING OUR MOTHER...
THAT I'M COMPLETELY
IRRESPONSIBLE
AND A STAY-IN-BED MOM.
- THAT DOESN'T EVEN
SOUND LIKE ME.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE MOM
OR BRUCE VILANCH.
COULD BE BRUCE VILANCH.
- THEN WHY WOULD SHE SAY IT?
- BECAUSE WE'RE GETTING ALONG.
- BECAUSE WE'RE FRIENDS AGAIN.
- YOU GOTTA REMEMBER--
MOM TYPICALLY HAS
NOTHING IN HER SYSTEM...
EXCEPT A BOTTLE OF VODKA
AND AN ESTROGEN PILL.
- SPEAKING OF WHICH--
narrator: MICHAEL AND LINDSAY
PROCEEDED TO DRINK...
AND AIR THEIR GRIEVANCES
ABOUT THEIR MOTHER.
- SHE'S ALWAYS TRYING
TO GET ME TO ADMIT THAT
MY MARRIAGE ISN'T WORKING.
- AND HOW'S IT GOING
WITH YOU AND TOBIAS?
- IT'S NOT WORKING.
AND THAT'S WHY I WANTED HER HELP
WITH MY CREDIT CARD DEBT.
I'M TRYING TO TAKE AT LEAST
SOME OF THE PRESSURE
OFF THIS MARRIAGE.
AND IF ANYTHING, IT'S WORSE NOW
THAT WE'RE SHARING A BEDROOM.
- YOU GUYS WERE NOT
SHARING A BEDROOM BEFORE?
- WELL, THE CUTOFFS
AREN'T EXACTLY A TURN-ON.
- YEAH, WHAT'S THE DEAL WITH THE
CUTOFFS?
- YOU'VE GOT TO PROMISE
NOT TO TELL ANYONE THIS.
- OKAY.
- HE'S A NEVER-NUDE.
- IS THAT EXACTLY
WHAT IT SOUNDS LIKE?
narrator: TOBIAS SUFFERED A RARE
PSYCHOLOGICAL AFFLICTION...
OF NEVER BEING ABLE
TO BE COMPLETELY NAKED.
- EXCUSE ME. DO THESE
EFFECTIVELY HIDE MY THUNDER?
- OH, I'M SORRY.
NO, I NEED YOU TO BE
COMPLETELY UNDRESSED.
- I AM COMPLETELY
UNDRESSED.
- I THOUGHT HE JUST LIKED
CUTOFFS.
- ME TOO.
WHAT ABOUT YOU? WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH YOUR LOVE LIFE?
HAVE YOU EVEN MET ANYONE
SINCE YOUR WIFE?
- THAT IS THE ONE SUBJECT
I AM NOT EAGER TO TALK ABOUT,
LINDSAY.
I LOVE MARTA.
- MOM'S HOUSEKEEPER?
- GOB'S GIRLFRIEND.
- OH, MY GOD.
- YEAH.
- LISTEN. YOU'RE A GREAT GUY,
AND IF SHE DOESN'T SEE THAT,
THEN SOMEONE ELSE WILL.
- YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE, LINDSAY?
YOU'RE GREAT.
AND I'M GONNA MOVE SOME
MONEY AROUND
IF IT'S GONNA
HELP YOU GET OUT OF DEBT.
YOU KNOW, I'D BE HAPPY TO DO
THAT.
- NO, MICHAEL.
- YEAH.
THE HELL WITH MOM.
AND HERE, MOM'S NEVER GONNA
GET BETWEEN US AGAIN.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY, BUSTER,
HAVING PAWNED OFF PLAYING ADAM,
WENT TO LUCILLE 2 TO ASK HER OUT
FOR CHRISTMAS EVE.
- THAT IS TERRIFIC 'CAUSE I GOT
TWO TICKETS TO THE PAGEANT!
- [clears throat] MY--MY
MOTHER'S GOING TO BE THERE.
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS TRYING TO PASS...
AS A MORE MUSCULAR BOY
THAN HE ACTUALLY WAS.
- ONE HUNDRED.
- ONE HUNDRED?
I HAD YOU AT 10.
- I DID SOME EARLIER IN THE DAY.
IT'S A RUNNING TOTAL.
SO WHAT'S WITH THE SUITCASE?
- IT'S A LITTLE TEST TO GET MY
PARENTS TO NOTICE ME.
YOU EVER GET THE FEELING
LIKE NO ONE EVEN SEES YOU?
- I'VE GOT A REALLY GOOD BODY,
SO...NO.
- HEY, GANG.
WHAT YOU DOING?
- JUST PACKING UP.
PACKING IT ON UP.
- UH-HUH.
LISTEN, CAN I TALK TO YOU
ALONE FOR A MOMENT?
- I'LL LEAVE YOU TWO ALONE HERE.
- OH, NO, GEORGE MICHAEL,
I MEANT YOU.
- MAEBY, CAN WE HAVE THE ROOM?
SO, AS YOU KNOW, I WAS HOPING TO
PLAY ADAM IN THIS THING,
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I AM NOT THREATENED.
- YOU KNOW, I'D BE HAPPY
TO LET YOU PLAY ADAM.
- GIVE ME THE SUIT.
GIVE ME THE SUIT.
- I'M ACTUALLY WEARING IT RIGHT
NOW, AND I CAN'T TELL YOU WHY.
- YOU'RE WEARING IT
RIGHT NOW?
- I HAVE TO WEAR IT ALL THE
TIME.
YOU'D NEVER UNDERSTAND.
- OH, PLEASE.
I'LL NEVER UNDER--
I'LL NEVER UNDERSTAND...
THAT YOU CAN NEVER BE NUDE?
I UNDERSTAND MORE THAN
YOU'LL NEVER KNOW.
- YIKES.
narrator: MICHAEL
FINALLY ARRANGED A MEETING
WITH ATTORNEY WAYNE JARVIS.
- LOOKING FOR A MORE
PROFESSIONAL APPROACH
TO OUR REPRESENTATION.
- WELL, I'M A PROFESSIONAL.
I'M SERIOUS,
AND I'M A PROFESSIONAL.
- THAT'S FANTASTIC.
SO HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN PRACTICING--
- I ALSO DON'T LIKE SMALL TALK.
I FIND THAT UNPROFESSIONAL.
WHY SHOULD I BE BILLING YOU
FOR SMALL TALK...
WHEN I'M ENJOYING IT
AS MUCH AS YOU ARE?
- THEN THIS MUST BE A FREEBIE
'CAUSE I'M HAVING A BALL.
- [chuckles] WHEN YOU'RE READY
TO GET SERIOUS, GIVE ME A CALL.
- NO, NO! NO, I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY.
I'M SERIOUS.
I'M READY.
- GOOD.
IF YOU RETAIN MY SERVICES,
I WILL GET YOUR FATHER
OUT OF JAIL,
AND WE WILL BE COUNTERSUING
BEFORE THE END OF THE YEAR.
WE'RE GONNA GET THIS COMPANY'S
NAME BACK TO WHERE IT STARTED.
- OR HOPEFULLY HIGHER.
- I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
DON'T HOLD ME TO THAT.
- I WON'T, AND I APPRECIATE THAT
TO A WONDERFUL DEGREE.
MY MOTHER
IS ON HER WAY UP HERE,
AND SHE'S RESISTANT TO THE IDEA
OF HIRING A NEW ATTORNEY.
IF SHE EVEN SEES YOU, SHE
PROBABLY WON'T COME IN THE ROOM.
- I SHALL DUCK BEHIND THE COUCH.
- WHAT A PRO.
[bell dings]
- MICHAEL.
- HI.
- I NEED TO GET THE MONEY TO GET
YOUR FATHER OUT FOR THE PAGEANT.
- ACTUALLY, THAT'S NOT WHY
I CALLED YOU HERE TODAY,
AND I'M NOT DOING THAT.
I GAVE THAT MONEY TO LINDSAY
TO PAY OFF HER CREDIT CARD DEBT.
- WHAT'D SHE DO, GET YOU DRUNK?
- NO, WE JUST, UH, WELL--
WE DID DRINK A LITTLE BIT.
HOW'D YOU KNOW THAT?
- BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT
SHE SAID SHE'D DO.
- I SAID YOU WOULDN'T GIVE HER
THE MONEY,
AND SHE SAID,
"HE WILL IF I GET HIM DRUNK."
PROBABLY BECAUSE SHE THINKS
YOU'RE A CHEAP BASTARD.
OH.
HER WORDS.
- SHE SET ME UP?
ALL THAT STUFF
ABOUT HER MARITAL TROUBLES
AND TOBIAS BEING A NEVER-NUDE?
- A NEVER-NUDE? I THOUGHT
HE JUST LIKED CUTOFFS.
- HOW DO YOU TREAT SOMEBODY
IN YOUR OWN FAMILY LIKE THAT,
LYING AND DECEIVING
AND SAYING ANYTHING
JUST TO GET YOUR OWN WAY?
- SO WHAT DID YOU WANT
TO SEE ME ABOUT?
- HMM?
OH, UM, THERE'S A BIG BOWL
OF CANDY IN MY OFFICE.
WHY DON'T YOU GO EAT IT?
- WAYNE JARVIS, ATTORNEY AT LAW.
I HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
TO TELL YOU THAT THERE IS
NO CANDY IN THIS OFFICE.
- LINDSAY.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I HAD TO GET AWAY FROM MARTA.
IF I HAVE TO SMELL ANOTHER MEAL
OF FISH, RICE AND MANGO,
I'M GONNA KILL SOMEBODY.
NOW MICHAEL'S LEARNING SPANISH.
WHAT'S UP WITH THAT?
- OH, WHO KNOWS?
HE WON'T GET YOUR FATHER
OUT OF JAIL FOR A NIGHT.
HE'S BRINGING IN
A NEW ATTORNEY.
- NEW ATTORNEY?
AND HE'S
LEARNING SPANISH?
HE'S HIDING SOMETHING.
AND I INTEND TO FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS.
- DO YOURSELF A FAVOR.
GET HIM DRUNK.
- [scoffs]
BARRY.
I SEE YOU'RE GETTING CLOSER
TO OUR ATTORNEY.
WELL, I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I WON'T BE NEEDING
YOUR HELP AFTER ALL.
MY BROTHER MICHAEL CAME THROUGH
AS HE ALWAYS DOES
AND AS YOU NEVER DO.
- WHATEVER IT TAKES TO GET
YOUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH THAT
NEVER-NUDE BACK ON TRACK.
- MICHAEL TOLD YOU THAT?
- HE COULDN'T WAIT TO.
narrator: AND LATER, WHILE
MICHAEL WAS MEETING WITH WAYNE--
- MY THING WITH TOBIAS WAS
A SECRET
LIKE YOU STEALING YOUR BROTHER'S
GIRLFRIEND, YOU LITTLE WEASEL!
I OPEN UP TO YOU,
AND YOU RUN AND TELL MOMMY!
- EXCUSE ME.
OUTSIDE, PLEASE.
THANK YOU. PARDON US.
LIKE IT ALL WASN'T JUST LIES
TO GET ME TO PAY THAT DEBT.
ISN'T THAT WHY YOU GOT ME DRUNK
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
- I GOT YOU DRUNK.
- MOM TOLD ME ABOUT
YOUR LITTLE PLAN.
- WHAT PLAN?
I HAD A GREAT TIME LAST NIGHT!
- SO DID I!
- THEN WHY ARE WE
YELLING AT EACH OTHER?
- MOM.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
- SHE DID IT AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT. WE'VE GOT
TO TEACH HER A LESSON.
- HMM.
- EXCUSE ME, WAYNE,
MY SISTER AND I WERE OUTSIDE
HAVING A BUSINESS DISCUSSION,
AND WE WERE WONDERING IF THERE'S
SOME SORT OF LEGAL WAY...
THAT WE CAN HUMILIATE
OUR MOTHER.
SOMETHING SHAMING,
SOMETHING PUBLIC.
I'VE USED ONE ADJECTIVE
TO DESCRIBE MYSELF.
WHAT IS IT?
- PROFESSIONAL.
- SO HOW ARE WE GOING
TO SCREW MOM?
- MAYBE WE CAN GET
BARRY TO HELP.
- FORGET IT.
I WAS RIGHT ABOUT THEM
ALL ALONG.
YOU KNOW BARRY'S
TAKING MOM TO THE PAGEANT?
- ON A DATE?
- YEAH.
- UGH! YOU KNOW, IF DAD COULD
SEE HER ON A DATE WITH BARRY,
HE'D GO CRAZY.
- WHICH WOULD ALLOW US
TO HIRE WAYNE.
- HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT
STAYING IN DEBT
JUST A LITTLE BIT LONGER?
narrator: SO THEY
DECIDED TO SPEND THE MONEY
MICHAEL HAD PROMISED LINDSAY..
TO GET THEIR FATHER OUT
FOR THE PAGEANT,
WHERE HE'D CATCH HIS WIFE ON A
DATE WITH BARRY.
MAEBY, TOO, CONTINUED TO TRY
TO TEACH HER PARENTS A LESSON.
- OKAY, SO I PRINTED THE FAKE
AIRLINE TICKET FROM MY COMPUTER.
IF MY PARENTS MISS THIS,
I REALLY MIGHT GO
TO SOUTH AMERICA.
- THAT SAYS "PORTUGAL."
- THAT'S RIGHT.
narrator: MAEBY'S PARENTS DIDN'T
FIND THE TICKET,
BUT GOB DID--
- "PORTUGAL."
narrator: WHICH CONFIRMED
HIS SUSPICIONS.
- GONNA LIVE IT UP DOWN OLD
SOUTH AMERICA WAY, HUH, MIKEY?
narrator: AND BUSTER FINALLY
GAVE IN TO LUCILLE 2'S WISHES.
- YOU READY TO SHOW ME OFF
BEFORE GOD AND THE WHOLE WORLD?
- IT'S NOT MY DAD'S REACTION
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
FINALLY SAW THE PAINTING
HE WAS GOING TO BE RE-CREATING.
- [singing]
AIN'T NO BIG THING, WOW
narrator: AND THEN WHAT
"FRONTSPIECE" MEANT.
- [singing] LOSING CONTROL
AIN'T NO BIG THING
WOW
narrator: GEORGE SR. GOT HIS 24
HOURS OF FREEDOM
AS THE PAGEANT FINALLY BEGAN.
- YOU KNOW, I SAW YOU
DO THIS WHEN I WAS A KID.
I WAS SO IMPRESSED.
YOU KNOW, YOU WERE
SO STILL AND GODLIKE.
IT WAS AT THAT MOMENT
THAT I KNEW I WOULD BE A DANCER.
- GLAD I COULD
MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
narrator: MICHAEL AND LINDSAY
SEARCHED THE CROWD
FOR THEIR MOTHER AND BARRY,
SO THEY COULD REVEL IN THE
PUBLIC SHAMING
THEY HAD ENGINEERED.
- MOM, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
narrator: BUT INSTEAD THEY FOUND
HER WITH WAYNE.
- I DON'T HAVE TO ANSWER THAT.
- I DON'T KNOW WHICH ONE OF YOU
I'M MORE DISAPPOINTED IN.
NO, IT'S WAYNE.
WAYNE--
- I HAVE NEEDS. I AM A MAN!
- HEY, WATCH--
- WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
YOUR FATHER DOESN'T
CARE ABOUT ME.
BARRY TELLS ME HE'S NOT EVEN
TRYING TO GET OUT OF PRISON.
- MOM, HE'S HERE. DAD'S HERE.
- HE'S HERE?
- YEAH, HE'S HERE.
WHY DID YOU DO THIS?
- WE WERE TRYING
TO TEACH YOU A LESSON.
- YOU IDIOTS!
IF HE SEES ME WITH WAYNE--
- WE'LL BE STUCK WITH BARRY.
- I SHALL DUCK BEHIND
THAT LITTLE GARBAGE CAR.
- GUY'S A PRO.
- AND NOW, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
MICHELANGELO'S
THE CREATION OF ADAM.
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
MADE HIS DEBUT--
- HEY, THAT'S MY--
YIKES.
BREAKING THE PAGEANT'S
CARDINAL RULE.
[crowd booing]
- HOW DARE HE!
- OH, STOP BOOING!
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG WITH IT.
THERE ARE DOZENS OF US.
DOZENS!
narrator: BUSTER ARRIVED
WITH LUCILLE AUSTERO...
AND NATURALLY ASSUMED
THE YELLS OF DISGUST
WERE DIRECTED TOWARD HIM.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
- BUSTER?
- OH, GOD! I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY, LUCILLE.
YEAH. LUCILLE.
MA, I'M SORRY!
- MAN!
THAT OLD LADY HAS REALLY DONE A
NUMBER ON YOU, HASN'T SHE?
narrator: BUT GEORGE MICHAEL
WASN'T THE ONLY PROBLEM WITH THE
PAINTING.
- WHERE IS GOD?
- THERE IS NO GOD!
- THERE GOES
MY CREDIT CARD PAYMENT.
- DAD!
DAD!
HEY! DAD!
- EXCUSE ME.
- DAD!
HEY, DAD, GET BACK HERE!
- NO! I'M NOT GOING BACK!
- DAD, COME HERE!
DAD!
- MICHAEL, I'M ONTO YOU.
THE SPANISH LESSONS,
THE LAWYER.
IF YOU'RE HEADING FOR PORTUGAL,
IT'S DUE SOUTH!
- WHAT?
NO, IT ISN'T.
DAD, YOU'RE NOT GONNA
OUTRUN ME IN THAT DRESS.
- LET GO! FOR GOD'S SAKES,
I'M NOT EVEN WEARING A JOCK.
- DAD, ARE YOU GOING TOO?
- NO ONE IS GOING TO PORTUGAL,
YOU IDIOT!
LINDSAY AND I BROKE DAD
OUT OF JAIL FOR A DAY
TO CATCH MOM ON A DATE.
- YOUR MOTHER
IS ON A DATE? OH.
- DAD!
- OH, OH.
[buzzing]
- DAD?
- narrator: AND SO,
MANY IN THE BLUTH FAMILY...
GATHERED TOGETHER FOR CHRISTMAS
EVE...AT PRISON.
- HEY, WHERE'D
YOUR MUSCLE SUIT GO?
- WAIT.
YOU KNEW?
- YEAH.
- I TOOK IT OFF.
- YOU DID?
YOU HAVE MADE SOME
TREMENDOUS STRIDES TODAY.
- EVER GET THE FEELING
LIKE YOU DON'T EVEN MATTER?
- ONLY WHEN I'M AROUND
MY CHILDREN.
- YOU REACH A CERTAIN AGE,
AND YOU HAVE TO PRACTICALLY
SCREAM TO GET NOTICED.
- THEY TURN YOU INTO A MONSTER,
AND THEN THEY CALL YOU ONE.
- I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE A MONSTER.
- AND I THINK
YOU'RE A LOVELY GIRL.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK YOU AND I OUGHT TO
SPEND MORE TIME TOGETHER.
- YEAH.
THAT'LL DRIVE THEM CRAZY.
- EXACTLY.
narrator: AND MICHAEL WAS FORCED
TO, ONCE AGAIN,
CALL IN THE COUNSEL
OF BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
- THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR COMING DOWN
ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
- OH, IT'S LIKE ANY OTHER DAY,
EXCEPT THAT I BILL DOUBLE.
SO, THEY'RE NOT
FILING CHARGES.
I GOT THEM TO CALL
YOUR FLEE FROM JUSTICE
"RELIGIOUS EXPRESSION."
- THIS IS A LAWYER.
- YEAH, HE'S-- HE'S VERY GOOD.
- AND YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO FORFEIT THAT BOND.
I WAS WAY OFF ABOUT THAT.
- THANKS AGAIN, MIKEY.
- CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
- SURE.
- ARE ALL THE GUYS IN HERE,
YOU KNOW--
- OH, NO, NO, NO.
NOT ALL OF THEM.
- YEAH. IT'S NEVER
THE ONES YOU HOPE.
- HOPE?
- THINK.
- HOW'D IT GO?
- WELL, THE BAD NEWS IS
YOU'RE IN DEBT AGAIN,
AND WE NEVER BUSTED MOM,
AND WE'RE STUCK WITH BARRY.
THE GOOD NEWS IS
WE'VE BEEN ASKED
NEVER TO PARTICIPATE IN THE
PAGEANT AGAIN.
- WELL, AT LEAST
WE'RE STILL PALS, HUH?
- YEAH.
THAT'S NOT REALLY
DOING IT FOR ME THIS TIME.
- YEAH.