narrator: NOW THE STORY OF A
WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL BLUTH WAS FED UP
WITH HIS MOTHER'S
EXTRAVAGANT SPENDING.
- HEY, MOM. REMEMBER WE HAD THAT
CONVERSATION ABOUT TRYING TO...
CUT BACK ON THINGS
THAT AREN'T NECESSITIES?
- LIKE IT WAS YESTERDAY.
- IT WAS THIS MORNING,
AND NOW I HEAR THAT YOU'VE HIRED
A CREW FOR THE YACHT.
I'M SELLING THAT YACHT.
- MICHAEL, YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
WHY I WANT IT.
TO THROW THE MOST LAVISH PARTY
THIS TOWN HAS EVER SEEN
FOR MY BIRTHDAY.
- I ENJOY BICENTENNIALS
AS MUCH AS THE NEXT GUY, MOM,
BUT WE'RE NOT DOING THAT.
- MY NEIGHBOR LUCILLE AUSTERO
IS CONSTANTLY THROWING PARTIES
FOR HERSELF.
SHE'S HAVING ANOTHER ONE
IN A WEEK.
- I'M NOT GOING TO THAT.
narrator: BUSTER HAD BEEN
AVOIDING LUCILLE AUSTERO
SINCE HE ACCIDENTALLY FLIRTED
WITH HER
WHILE NOT WEARING HIS GLASSES.
AND THEN ACCIDENTALLY BID
ON HER
AT A CHARITY
BACHELORETTE AUCTION.
- TEN THOUSAND DOLLARS!
- BUSTER.
narrator: AND THEN ACCIDENTALLY
ENTERED HER APARTMENT,
THINKING IT WAS HIS MOTHER'S.
- I NEED YOU RIGHT NOW.
[gasps]
- FELLAS, TAKE A POWDER.
- OH, HERE COMES THE 10:15
CONNIPTION, RIGHT ON TIME.
HONEST TO GOD, BUSTER,
IT'S LIKE EVERY LITTLE THING
MAKES YOU SEIZE UP IN TERROR
LATELY.
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE YOU GET THAT FROM.
GET AWAY FROM THAT STOVE.
YOU'RE GOING TO
LIGHT YOUR HAIR ON FIRE.
HE'S WEAK.
- SPEAKING OF WEAK, MOM, WHAT DO
YOU GOT IN THERE, GOLD BARS?
- PROTEIN BARS FOR YOUR FATHER.
HE'S PUMPING UP IN PRISON.
- NO MORE PARTIES.
OKAY, MOM?
- YOU'RE MY THIRD
LEAST-FAVORITE CHILD.
- I CAN LIVE WITH THAT.
narrator: MICHAEL CAME HOME
TO FIND HIS MOTHER'S
FOURTH LEAST-FAVORITE CHILD.
- HEARD YOU'RE SELLING THE
YACHT.
- YEAH. I HAD A COUPLE
IN THERE THIS MORNING.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
- WELL, THEY GOT
THE ASIAN RIGHT.
"HOTTIES" MIGHT BE
A STRETCH.
WELL, LET'S START
WITH THE LITTLE ONE.
- YOU'RE NOT STAYING ON
THE YACHT, ARE YOU?
- WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO,
MICHAEL?
LIVE FULL-TIME WITH MARTA?
- OR BREAK UP WITH HER.
I'M SURE THERE'D BE
SOMEBODY ELSE OUT THERE
THAT WOULD APPRECIATE HER.
narrator: IN FACT, MICHAEL FELT
THAT MAN WAS HIMSELF.
HE HAD BECOME INFATUATED
WITH HIS BROTHER'S GIRLFRIEND.
AND WAS HAVING DIFFICULTY
KEEPING HIS LOVE A SECRET.
YOU HAVE 48 HOURS
TO VACATE THE YACHT.
- GUYS, I'VE GOT A GREAT IDEA.
I WANNA THROW MOM A PARTY.
- WOULD YOU--I JUST TOLD MOM
NO MORE PARTIES.
- I KNOW, MICHAEL.
THAT'S WHY THIS IS THE PERFECT
OPPORTUNITY
TO THROW HER A SURPRISE PARTY.
SHE'D NEVER SUSPECT IT.
- IS THIS HER SUGGESTION?
- NO. I JUST THINK IT'S
IMPORTANT TO HONOR YOUR PARENTS.
- WHY DON'T YOU START
BY VISITING DAD IN JAIL?
YOU'VE NEVER EVEN BEEN THERE.
- MICHAEL, DO YOU HAVE
ANY IDEA WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF I WERE TO VISIT PRISON?
- HMM.
- IT WOULD BE PANDEMONIUM.
- MM-HMM.
- IT'D JUST GIVE DAD
ONE MORE REASON TO THINK...
THAT I'VE GOT NOTHING
TO OFFER BUT MY LOOKS.
- YEAH, I GOT SOME OF THAT...
EXCEPT HE ALSO DIDN'T LIKE
MY LOOKS.
- OKAY, MICHAEL.
I WILL GO VISIT DAD,
IF YOU DRIVE MOM TO THE
RESTAURANT
FOR THE SURPRISE PARTY.
- I'LL JUST PRETEND THAT
I'M TAKING HER OUT THAT EVENING.
COME ON.
THAT WOULD NEVER HAPPEN.
- WELL, SHE CERTAINLY CAN'T
DRIVE HERSELF.
I MEAN, SHE'S
THE WORLD'S WORST DRIVER.
narrator: LINDSAY WAS NOT
EXAGGERATING.
LUCILLE HAD RECENTLY
BEEN FEATURED ON FOX'S
WORLD'S WORST DRIVERS.
- YEAH.
I CAN'T BELIEVE SHE GOT THAT
DRIVER'S LICENSE RENEWED.
- SHE DIDN'T.
I DUMMIED HER UP A NEW ONE.
NOT MY BEST WORK THOUGH.
SHE WANTED TO LOOK 48.
I NEARLY AIRBRUSHED HER
INTO OBLIVION.
WE ENDED UP CHECKING
"ALBINO" ON THE FORM.
- COME ON, MICHAEL.
WHO KNOWS HOW LONG OUR PARENTS
ARE GOING TO BE AROUND.
- YEAH, WELL I GOTTA TELL YA.
I WAS OVER AT HER PLACE TODAY,
AND SHE LOOKED
A LITTLE FRAIL TO ME.
SHE WAS HAVING TROUBLE
EVEN LIFTING UP THIS BAG OF
GROCERIES.
ALL RIGHT.
WE WILL DO THE SURPRISE PARTY.
- FOR GANGY?
- YEAH, HOW DID YOU KNOW?
- SHE CALLED AND INVITED US.
- OKAY, SO IT WAS HER IDEA.
- WE DON'T HAVE TO GO, DO WE?
- COME ON.
THIS IS
A BLUTH FAMILY CELEBRATION.
IT'S NO PLACE FOR CHILDREN.
narrator: AND LINDSAY WENT TO
THE PRISON TO VISIT
HER FATHER FOR THE FIRST TIME.
BUT DIDN'T GET THE RECEPTION
SHE WAS EXPECTING.
- I WANNA THANK YOU FOR COMING
HERE.
IT TOOK A LOT OF GUTS.
- THE REASON I'M HERE TODAY
IS BECAUSE I FELT THAT
I NEEDED TO SAY SOMETHING.
- OH, OKAY.
- MY WHOLE LIFE,
ALL YOU'VE EVER PRAISED ME FOR
IS MY LOOKS.
- OH, NO. YOUR LOOKS--
- YES, DAD.
I MEAN, IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
MICHAEL'S GOT THE BRAINS,
GOB'S GOT THE CHARM,
BUSTER'S GOT THE--
- HIGH-FASTENING PANTS.
- HAVE YOU SAID THAT?
- NO. I'M SAYING THAT NOW.
- SO, ANYWAY.
LOOK, IF YOU'RE WONDERING WHY
I HAVEN'T VISITED,
MAYBE IT'S BECAUSE I WANTED TO
BE THOUGHT OF
AS MORE THAN
JUST A BEAUTIFUL FACE.
AND A GORGEOUS HEAD OF HAIR.
narrator: LINDSAY WAS
SURPRISED ONCE AGAIN
THAT NO HEADS WERE TURNED.
- [scoffs]
I'M GONNA GO SHOPPING.
I'LL BE BACK TOMORROW.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS FINALLY MOVING
BEYOND
HIS CRUSH ON MAEBY...
AND FELT HAPPY TO HAVE A COUSIN
HE COULD JUST SEE A MOVIE WITH.
- IT WAS A LOVE
BETWEEN TWO COUSINS
THAT THE WORLD THOUGHT WAS
WRONG.
BUT IT WAS THE WORLD
THAT WAS WRONG.
- [speaking French]
- WE HAVE GOT TO
SEE THIS MOVIE.
- EXCUSE ME, KIDS?
CAN I SEE YOUR I.D.'S?
narrator:
AND MICHAEL WAS DRIVING HIS
MOTHER TO HER SURPRISE PARTY.
- WHERE ON EARTH
ARE WE GOING?
LEFT AT THE NEXT CORNER.
YOU KNOW, MICHAEL?
- YEAH?
- I'D BE HAPPY TO DRIVE
IF YOU WANT ME TO.
IT'S BETTER THAN SITTING HERE
WITH BUSTER'S STUPID ROCK
BEHIND ME.
narrator: BUSTER HAD RECENTLY
BROUGHT THE ROCK HOME...
FROM AN ARCHEOLOGICAL DIG,
BUT HAD YET TO FIND A WAY
TO GET IT OUT OF THE CAR.
- MOM, YOU'VE ALREADY GOT
TWO STRIKES ON YOUR RECORD.
YOU STRIKE ONE MORE PERSON,
AND IT'S TECHNICALLY A SPREE.
- ARE WE GOING TO THE BACK?
IS THIS WHAT I THINK IT IS?
- SURPRISE!
narrator:
AND SHE WAS SURPRISED...
THAT HER FAMILY DIDN'T SHOW UP.
- SO THIS IS WHAT
MY CHILDREN THINK OF ME.
- [singing] MORE FICTION THAN
IT'S FACT
BUT BELIEVE IT OR NOT
MY MOTHER DEAR
DECIDED SHE'D COME BACK
AS A CAR--
[tv clicks off]
- WHERE THE-- [beep]
WAS EVERYBODY?
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- MOM'S PARTY.
WHERE WERE YOU GUYS?
- IT'S THE FIRST
I'VE HEARD ABOUT IT.
- WHAT ABOUT YOU? NEIMAN'S?
- PRISON.
THEN NEIMAN'S.
BUT ONLY BECAUSE I'M GOING BACK
TO PRISON,
AND THEY'VE SEEN ME IN THIS.
- BUSTER? YOU OF ALL PEOPLE.
WHERE WERE YOU, BUDDY?
YOU BARELY EVEN LEAVE
MOM'S APARTMENT.
narrator:
IN FACT, BUSTER WAS WORRIED
ABOUT RUNNING INTO LUCILLE 2.
SO HE NEVER LEFT
HIS MOTHER'S APARTMENT.
LUCILLE 2 WAS
ALSO SUPPOSED TO GO,
BUT WAS WAITING UNTIL
SHE SAW BUSTER EMERGE.
- TONIGHT,
MOTHER WAS HUMILIATED.
AND I WANNA THROW HER ANOTHER
SURPRISE PARTY--A REAL ONE.
ONE WHERE SHE'S NOT THE ONE
THAT'S YELLING "SURPRISE."
- MOM YELLED "SURPRISE"?
- YEAH. SHE WENT FROM GIDDY
TO DEVASTATED.
I MEAN, IT WOULD'VE BEEN FUNNY
IF IT WASN'T SO--
WELL, IT WAS KIND OF FUNNY.
- WHAT FRAIL ACT GOT YOU
THIS TIME, MICHAEL?
SHE COULDN'T OPEN A JAR?
WHAT, DID A CLUMP OF HER HAIR
COME OUT IN YOUR HANDS?
- [laughs]
- NO. IT WAS SOMETHING THAT
SHE SAID AT DINNER.
- IT'S DRY.
- YOU KNOW, MOM, I'M SORRY
YOU'RE UPSET.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
IF YOU WERE NICER,
THEN MAYBE YOUR KIDS WOULD TAKE
BETTER CARE OF YOU, YOU KNOW?
OR--OR WANNA BE WITH YOU MORE.
- I'VE BEEN
A HORRIBLE MOTHER.
- NO, MOM.
YOU'RE GREAT.
YOU'VE BEEN A GREAT MOTHER.
- WELL, YOU KNOW SHE'S BEEN
A HORRIBLE MOTHER, RIGHT?
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL ME.
BUT WHAT WAS I GONNA SAY?
ALL RIGHT? SO, IT'S A PARTY.
I MEAN, IF YOU'RE NOT GONNA DO
IT FOR MOM, DO IT FOR ME.
- OKAY. BUT I THINK
A PARTY'S A LITTLE EXCESSIVE.
- UM, IS IT OKAY IF I DO IT FOR
MOM AND NOT YOU?
- YEAH.
- 'CAUSE I REALLY LIKE MOM.
- WE KNOW.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY,
BUSTER DECIDED IT WAS TIME TO
DEAL WITH...
THE SITUATION WITH
LUCILLE AUSTERO.
- I'VE ALREADY GOT
A LUCILLE IN MY LIFE.
- I UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S HEALTHY.
- I DIDN'T MEAN TO
LEAD YOU ON.
- OH, BUSTER, I FEEL SO FOOLISH.
- NO.
- YES. I'M FOOLISH
AND I'M FUNNY AND I'M NEEDY.
AM I NEEDY?
- NO.
- ARE YOU SURE I'M NOT NEEDY?
'CAUSE I FEEL NEEDY SOMETIMES.
- YOU KNOW, WE'RE PROBABLY
NOT THAT DIFFERENT, YOU AND ME.
YOU AND I.
IS IT "I" OR IS IT "ME"?
- BUSTER, IT'S US.
- YES. IT IS US. US.
[both chuckle nervously]
narrator:
UNDER THE PRETENSE OF DRIVING
HIS MOTHER SOMEWHERE ELSE,
MICHAEL, ONCE AGAIN,
ARRIVED AT THE RESTAURANT.
- MICHAEL, DID YOU
DO THIS AGAIN?
- SURPRISE!
narrator: AND ONCE AGAIN,
NO ONE SHOWED UP.
- GET UP.
- I TOLD YOU.
THEY DON'T SUPPORT ME.
- I HATE TO TELL YOU, MOM, BUT
THEY DON'T SUPPORT ME EITHER.
I SAT DOWN AND I TOLD THEM
THIS WAS IMPORTANT TO ME.
- YOU DID THAT FOR ME?
- I LET YOU DRIVE,
DIDN'T I?
- YES, YOU DID, MICHAEL,
AND I'M LOVING IT.
YOU'RE A GOOD SON.
YOU ALWAYS DO THINGS
FOR OTHERS.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
HOLDING THIS FAMILY TOGETHER.
- AND YOU SEE A LOT MORE THAN
I GIVE YOU CREDIT FOR, MOM.
YOU'RE NOT JUST CONCERNED
WITH YOURSELF.
YOU CARE ABOUT THE FAMILY.
HEY.
IS THAT GOB?
- IT'S AN IDIOT ON A SCOOTER
AT NIGHT? IT'S GOTTA BE GOB.
LET'S GIVE HIM A SCARE.
- HMM?
NO, MOM.
I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD.
- A NICE LITTLE SCARE.
[revs engine]
HEY, BIG SHOT, TOO BUSY TO
GO TO YOUR MOTHER'S PARTY?
- MOM, THAT IS NOT GOB.
MOM! MOM!
- [tires screech]
[static]
- YOU OKAY, SIR?
- [groans]
YEAH. I GUESS.
HOW'S MY MOM? SHE'S SO FRAIL.
- I'M FINE. I'M FINE.
I WAS THROWN CLEAR.
I ONLY CARE ABOUT YOU.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
- ACTUALLY, MY HEAD
DOES NOT HURT AT ALL.
WHAT DID YOU GIVE ME?
- YOUR MOTHER ASKED ME TO
PUMP YOU FULL OF--
- CHILDREN'S ASPIRIN.
- OKAY.
- YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY.
I REMEMBER, UM,
LEAVING THE RESTAURANT.
AND THEN, UH,
I WAS DRIVING, I GUESS.
I-I JUST--
I CANNOT PICTURE IT.
- THAT'S PRETTY COMMON,
ACTUALLY.
IT'S JUST SHORT-TERM
MEMORY LOSS
FROM THE BUMP
ON THE BACK OF YOUR HEAD.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE I DID THIS.
[sighs] MY INSURANCE RATES
ARE GONNA GO THROUGH THE ROOF.
- THAT'S NOT WHAT MATTERS NOW.
HERE, GET COMFORTABLE.
SCOOT UP.
- "SCOOT"? SCOOTER.
WAS THERE A SCOOTER INVOLVED?
- [gasps]
OH, DEAR.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I DID THAT.
I AM SO SORRY.
I'LL GET YOU SOME AIR.
- I HARDLY FELT IT.
IN FACT, ACTUALLY, UH,
I DIDN'T FEEL IT.
[glass shatters]
WHAT WAS THAT?
- BUSTER, DO YOU REMEMBER
WHEN WE WERE KISSING LAST NIGHT?
- IT WAS A WILD, WILD RIDE.
BUT IS THIS SOMETHING
WE CAN DO?
IS THIS SOMETHING
SOCIETY WILL ALLOW?
- I DON'T CARE WHAT
OTHER PEOPLE THINK.
MY GOD, FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN YEARS
I FELT LIKE I WAS STANDING ON
SOLID GROUND.
- YOU KNOW,
MY PANIC ATTACKS HAVE DECREASED.
I FEEL CONFIDENT.
I'M FEELING PROUD EVEN.
[giggles]
I MEAN, FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN MY LIFE--
[gasps]
- I'LL CALL DR. MILLER.
[cell phone ringing]
- OH. EXCUSE ME.
HELLO. OH, MY GOD.
I'M GETTING MY GAUZE.
- YOU KNOW, I SHOULD CALL
GEORGE MICHAEL.
I'M WORRIED ABOUT MY SON.
- I'M WORRIED ABOUT MY SON.
GEORGE MICHAEL WILL BE FINE
WITH HIS AUNT AND UNCLE.
I WANT YOU RESTING,
NOT USING THE PHONE.
LET ME TAKE CARE OF YOU.
- YOU KNOW, YOU REALLY ARE MORE
GENEROUS THAN I CAN REMEMBER.
BUT THAT'S WHAT A PARENT DOES,
HUH?
YOU PUT YOUR KID FIRST?
- REST UP, SWEETIE.
YOU GAVE ME QUITE A SCARE.
- SCARE. DID SOMEBODY SAY,
"LET'S GIVE HIM A SC--"
[gasps]
- WHAT IS THE MATTER WITH ME?
CLUMSY CLARA.
- TOTALLY COOL.
DIDN'T FEEL A THING.
YOU KNOW, MOM,
I'M CRAZY ABOUT THIS ASPIRIN.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE GIVE IT TO CHILDREN.
narrator: GOB, MEANWHILE,
WAS BEING VISITED BY
MICHAEL'S SON, GEORGE MICHAEL.
- MICHAEL?
GEORGE MICHAEL.
YOU'VE GOTTA GO.
- WAIT.
[water splashes]
- UNCLE GOB, IS THIS A BAD TIME?
- NO. ARE YOU KIDDING?
SO, WHAT'S UP?
- I, UH, NEED YOU TO MAKE SOME
FAKE I.D.'S FOR ME AND MAEBY.
- LIKE A PASSPORT?
- YEAH, YEAH.
THAT'D BE GREAT.
OH, AND, UH,
PREFERABLY FRENCH.
I LIKE THE WAY THEY THINK.
- LOOK, I DON'T WANT YOU
THINKING THAT YOUR UNCLE IS SOME
SLEAZY CHARACTER FROM THE DOCKS.
GOOD MORNING.
- HOW ARE YOU?
- SHE'S AN OLYMPIAN...
HOPEFUL.
SWIMMING AND SOME COACHING.
YES, I WILL MAKE
THE I.D.'S FOR YOU.
BUT WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO
MAKE THIS QUICK.
YOUR DAD
WANTS ME OUT OF HERE BY NOON.
- OH, NO, I WOULDN'T WORRY ABOUT
HIM. HE'S STAYING AT GANGY'S.
YEAH, HE GOT IN A CAR ACCIDENT
ON THE WAY BACK FROM
HER BIRTHDAY PARTY.
- OH, MAN, I TOLD HIM
NOT TO LET HER DRIVE.
- NO. IT WAS HIM DRIVING.
SHE'S TAKING GOOD CARE OF
HIM TOO.
SHE WON'T EVEN
LET HIM USE THE PHONE.
- SO YOU'RE TELLING ME THAT HE
CAN'T GO ANYWHERE AND
HE'S INCOMMUNICADO?
- RIGHT.
narrator: THAT'S WHEN
GOB DECIDED TO TAKE THE YACHT
TO SOUTH AMERICA FOR THE SUMMER.
- I GOTTA ALERT
THIS BOAT'S CREW.
THEY'LL BE DEVASTATED.
narrator: LINDSAY PUT ON HER NEW
OUTFIT AND RETURNED TO PRISON.
BACK AT LUCILLE'S,
MICHAEL WAS STILL
PIECING TOGETHER THE ACCIDENT.
- HEY, BUSTER.
- HEY, BROTHER.
- DR. MILLER?
- YEAH.
I JUST JUMPED THROUGH A PLATE
GLASS WINDOW ON A DATE. [laughs]
- OH. WELL,
WOMEN LOVE TO LAUGH.
- IT WAS WORTH IT
TO BE AWAY FROM
MOM'S CONTROLLING GRASP.
- BUSTER, WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR HEAD?
- NOTHING.
GOB WAS JUST TEACHING ME
HOW TO HIT IT WITH A HAMMER.
- GOB WAS THERE.
GOB WAS ON HIS SCOOTER.
[gasps] I THINK I WANTED TO
HIT GOB.
- YES. THAT IS EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU WANTED TO
GIVE GOB A SCARE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY.
- I THINK I DO.
THANKS, MOM.
narrator: GEORGE SENIOR WAS,
ONCE AGAIN,
BEING VISITED BY HIS DAUGHTER.
THAT'S IT. I DON'T WANT--
YOU CAN'T--I DON'T--
PLEASE, YOU GOTTA STOP
COMING HERE.
- IT IS OBVIOUS
I'M NOT WEARING A BRA, RIGHT?
- I CAN'T TAKE THIS ANYMORE.
I, UM--UH, I'M PAYING
FAR TOO BIG A PRICE FOR THIS.
- WELL, WHAT ABOUT ME?
THIS IS THE THIRD TIME
I'VE COME HERE.
I HAVEN'T EVEN BEEN
REMOTELY HARASSED.
- THAT IS NOT WHAT I'M PAYING
FOR.
- HAVE I LOST IT?
DID I EVER EVEN HAVE IT?
- I'M PAYING THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS IN KRUGERRANDS.
- WHAT?
- GOLD. KRUGERRANDS.
YOUR MOTHER SNUCK 'EM IN HERE
STUFFED IN ENERGY BAR
WRAPPERS...
TO KEEP ME FROM GETTING
STRANGLED
IN THE SHOWER OR WORSE.
- STABBED?
- IN A WAY.
I USED THEM TO PAY OFF
THE OTHER GUYS.
TO STOP THEM FROM HOLLERING
OBSCENITIES
AT MY--MY LITTLE GIRL.
BUT YOU KEEP COMING BACK HERE,
HONEY, AND I'M GOING BROKE.
- THAT'S ALL I EVER WANTED
FROM YOU, DADDY.
FOR YOU TO
SPEND MONEY ON ME.
- NO TOUCHING!
- GOB, I WANT YOU TO
MOVE BACK ON TO THE YACHT.
- THE YACHT?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I'D WANT TO NOW?
- WELL, I KNOW THAT
YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR--
[horn blows]
WHAT WAS THAT?
- I THINK THAT WAS ON
YOUR END.
- THE TRUTH IS, I CAN WAIT
ON SELLING THE YACHT.
IT'S JUST MONEY, RIGHT?
- WOW. HOW HARD DID YOU HIT
THAT STEERING WHEEL?
- I ACTUALLY HIT
THE BACK OF MY HEAD.
- THE BACK OF YOUR HEAD?
- YEAH. GOB, THE ACCIDENT
ONLY HAPPENED BECAUSE...
I WAS TRYING TO SCARE YOU.
MAYBE EVEN HURT YOU.
- THAT DOESN'T SOUND LIKE YOU.
IT SOUNDS LIKE MOM.
- CAN WE PLEASE JUST LAY
OFF MOM FOR A CHANGE?
SHE'S THE ONE THAT HELPED ME
REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED.
I'M THE BAD GUY HERE.
NOT HER.
AND DEFINITELY NOT YOU,
SO, WOULD YOU PLEASE
JUST TAKE THE YACHT?
- I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
SOUTH AMERICA SOUNDS GOOD.
BUT A CHANCE TO EXPOSE MOM?
TURN THIS SKIFF AROUND.
- WE HAVEN'T EVEN
LEFT THE DOCK.
- BUT "SKIFF" IS
APPROPRIATE, RIGHT?
narrator: GOB RUSHED TO SHORE
TO SPARE HIS BROTHER...
FROM WHAT HE WAS CERTAIN
WERE HIS MOTHER'S MACHINATIONS.
-  WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- HEY. OPEN THIS DOOR.
- YOU'VE BEEN SET UP.
- MICHAEL!
- THERE'S NO WAY YOU WERE TRYING
TO HURT ME.
YOU DON'T HATE ME.
MOM HATES ME.
YOU KIND OF LIKE ME.
- YEAH. I KIND OF LIKE YOU.
- YEAH.
- MICHAEL, I NEED YOUR HELP.
- COMING.
OW! I GOT HIT BACK THERE.
- RIGHT!
ON THE BACK OF THE HEAD,
WHICH MEANS THAT YOU COULDN'T
HAVE HIT THE STEERING WHEEL.
MOM MUST HAVE CLUBBED YOU
WITH A CHAMPAGNE BOTTLE
OR SOMETHING SO SHE COULD DRIVE.
- GOB, HOW'D YOU
FIGURE IT OUT?
- WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT, IT'S
FUNNY YOU SHOULD ASK THAT--
- NO. HE DIDN'T FIGURE
ANYTHING OUT.
I PROBABLY GOT HIT ON
THE BACK OF THE HEAD
BECAUSE OF BUSTER'S ROCK.
- HEY, BIG SHOT!
[knocking]
- WHICH WAS BEHIND
THE PASSENGER SEAT.
- WHICH MEANS THAT SHE PICKED
YOU UP
AND DRAGGED YOU OVER
TO THE DRIVER'S SEAT.
- MOM CAN'T PICK ME UP.
SHE COULD BARELY PICK UP
THAT BAG OF PROTEIN BARS.
- GUESS WHAT?
THEY WEREN'T PROTEIN BARS.
THEY WERE GOLD KRUGERRANDS.
AND DAD FINALLY PAID ATTENTION
TO MY INTELLECT.
- OPEN THIS DOOR!
- GOB, THIS IS NUTS.
MOTHER IS FRAIL.
[clattering]
- STOP THIS NONSENSE
THIS INSTANT!
- YOU SET HIM UP, MOM.
I WAS HALFWAY TO SOUTH AMERICA,
BUT I COULDN'T LET YOU
GET AWAY WITH IT...
BECAUSE WE'RE BROTHERS, MOM,
AND WE KIND OF LIKE EACH OTHER.
- YOU WERE GOING TO
SOUTH AMERICA?
- I DON'T THINK SO.
- MOM, YOU AND I
WERE GETTING ALONG SO WELL.
I WAS THINKING SO HIGHLY OF YOU.
HOW COULD YOU MAKE ME THINK
THIS WAS ALL MY FAULT?
- BECAUSE IF YOU KNEW
IT WAS MY FAULT,
YOU WOULD'VE TURNED AGAINST ME.
AND I HAD FINALLY
GOTTEN YOU ON MY SIDE.
YOU WERE STICKING UP FOR ME.
I-I DON'T EVEN REMEMBER
YOU EVER DOING THAT BEFORE.
I JUST WANT MY CHILDREN
TO LOVE ME.
- STOP LYING. STOP MANIPULATING.
JUST BE NICER.
- BUT--
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M A HORRIBLE MOTHER.
- NO, NO, MOM.
YOU'RE GREAT.
- THAT'S CRAZY TALK.
- YOU'RE A FANTASTIC MOTHER.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
WHAT I'M HEARING, MOTHER.
- OH, WE DO.
WE REALLY LOVE YOU.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
GEORGE MICHAEL AND MAEBY SNEAK
BACK INTO LES COUSINS DANGEREUX.
- EXCUSE ME.
YOU'RE TOO YOUNG TO BE
HOLDING THAT TICKET.
- LET'S GO.
- I CAN'T GO TO JAIL.
- LET'S JUST WATCH CARTOONS.
- SIR, WE WILL NOT BE
STARTING WITH LES COUSINS...
- UNTIL YOU LEAVE.
- EXCUSE ME, BUT I THOUGHT
MY A.A.R.P. CARD...
WAS GOOD FOR ONE AND A GUEST.
- YOU KNOW WHAT? I KNEW SOCIETY
WOULD NEVER ACCEPT THIS.
AND THEY NEVER WILL.
narrator: MICHAEL'S
INSURANCE TAKES ANOTHER HIT.
[grunts]
- [groans]
OW!
- I WAS DEFINITELY DRIVING
THAT TIME.