- male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
BEFORE GOING TO WORK,
MICHAEL DECIDED
TO HAVE A LITTLE FUN.
- I'M DOING A LITTLE
COST-PROJECTION ANALYSIS
FOR A MINI-MALL.
- WOW.
IT'S PRETTY COOL YOU KNOW HOW
TO DO ALL THAT STUFF.
- YEAH, WELL,
MAYBE YOUR OLD MAN
IS JUST A LITTLE BIT COOLER
THAN YOU THOUGHT HE WAS.
STUPID. STUPID CHAIR.
VERY STUPID CHAIR.
BUT IT'S ALSO THIS STUPID
MODEL HOME FURNITURE.
MAYBE I OUGHTA GET MYSELF
ONE OF THOSE
NICE LEATHER CHAIRS FROM WORK.
- PEOPLE CAN TAKE
CHAIRS HOME FROM WORK?
- WELL, NOT EVERYBODY.
BUT I'M THE PRESIDENT
OF THE BLUTH COMPANY
SINCE DAD'S IN JAIL.
IT'S OKAY IF I TAKE A LITTLE
SOMETHING FROM WORK, YOU KNOW?
- YEAH, BUT ISN'T THAT
WHY GRANDPA'S IN JAIL,
BECAUSE
HE TOOK THINGS FROM WORK?
- YOU'RE A GOOD KID,
YOU KNOW THAT?
- I MEAN, A CHAIR COSTS MONEY,
SO IT'S LIKE STEALING,
AND YOU ALWAYS SAY--
- NOT STEALING. NOT.
OKAY, I'M THE ONE
THAT TAUGHT YOU
THAT STEALING IS BAD,
ALL RIGHT?
I'M JUST SAYING, YOU KNOW,
IF I GOT A LEATHER CHAIR, OKAY?
AND I GET TO LEAN BACK--
OH, THIS ONE'S GONNA GO.
thump!
[groans]
- LEATHER CHAIR?
SO YOU'RE AGAINST STEALING,
BUT SKINNING COWS
IS COOL WITH YOU.
- I'M FINE, BY THE WAY.
FRANKLY, YOUR CONCERN
IS GETTING EMBARRASSING.
- SINCE WHEN ARE YOU
AGAINST LEATHER?
- YEAH, YOU'RE NOT EVEN
A VEGETARIAN.
- I'M NOT AGAINST THE INSIDES.
PEOPLE NEED MEAT TO SURVIVE.
- YOU ARE AWARE
THAT THEY DON'T
REMOVE IT
FROM THE COW SURGICALLY, RIGHT?
[doorbell rings]
- HI, MICHAEL.
- MARTA, HI.
HEY, IT'S MARTA.
HEY, IT'S MARTA, EVERYBODY.
GREAT TO SEE YOU.
- I WAS JUST
LOOKING FOR GOB.
- WELL,
YOU'RE HIS GIRLFRIEND.
- narrator: MICHAEL WISHED MARTA
WAS HIS GIRLFRIEND,
A SECRET HE HAD
ONLY SHARED WITH LINDSAY.
- ACTUALLY, WE HAD A BIG FIGHT.
HE THOUGHT I WAS
BELITTLING HIS CAREER,
BUT I NEVER WOULD DO THAT.
- NEITHER WOULD I.
WHAT CAREER?
- THE MAGIC?
- OH, THE TRICKS,
THE LITTLE TRICKS.
THOSE ARE GREAT.
- WELL, HE DIDN'T LIKE
MY REACTION TO HIS NEW ONE.
- REAL NEEDLE. REAL APPLE.
REAL NECK.
- AH, EL ES ZOMBI!
[screaming]
- THEY'RE CHILDREN!
HOW COULD YOU DO THAT?
- OH, SURE.
FIRST YOU DUMP ALL OVER IT.
NOW YOU WANT TO KNOW
HOW IT'S DONE.
- AND I WANTED TO APOLOGIZE.
- WELL, HE HASN'T
BEEN HERE.
- BUT HE SAID
HE WAS STAYING HERE.
OH, MY GOD.
MAYBE HE'S STAYING
WITH ANOTHER WOMAN.
- NO, NO, NO. NO, NO, NO.
NO, HE IS STAYING HERE.
I JUST HAVEN'T SEEN HIM HERE,
THE FOYER OR THE KITCHEN.
- WELL, THAT'S A RELIEF.
- YEAH.
- WELL, TELL HIM
TO CALL ME WHEN HE GETS IN.
- I SURE WILL, MARTA.
- IF YOU REMEMBER.
- I WILL REMEMBER.
YEAH. I'LL GIVE HIM
THE MESSAGE THOUGH. OKAY.
- SHE'S GONE.
- YEP. GOT IT.
- YOU ARE TOO NICE.
- OH, COME ON.
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED TO DO?
TELL HER THAT GOB
IS NOT STAYING HERE?
TELL HER GOB
IS SCREWING AROUND ON HER?
GOD KNOWS WHERE HE IS?
ACTUALLY,
THAT-THAT SOUNDED OKAY.
- NAH, YOU'LL NEVER
BE ABLE TO DO IT.
YOU'RE TOO GOOD.
YOU'RE THE NOBLE ONE.
- THANK YOU.
- THE ONE WHO NEVER WINS.
- I-I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
- THE LOSER.
- HMM?
- THE FOOL.
- SHE IS SUCH A HYPOCRITE.
DOESN'T IT DRIVE YOU NUTS?
- CRAZY. WAIT.
WHO IS? WHICH PART?
- MY MOM.
SHE PRETENDS TO CARE
ABOUT ALL THESE CAUSES.
- narrator: LINDSAY HAD ALWAYS
BEEN CELEBRATED
FOR HER WINE AND CHEESE
CHARITY FUND-RAISERS.
- I MEAN,
NOW SHE'S ANTI-LEATHER?
LET'S SEE HOW SHE FEELS
WHEN HER DAUGHTER'S PRO-LEATHER.
WANNA GO SHOPPING WITH ME?
I BET YOU COULD
GET SOMETHING COOL.
- narrator: IN FACT,
GEORGE MICHAEL
HAD BEEN TRYING
TO PROVE TO MAEBY
THAT HE WAS MACHO,
AFTER AN EMBARRASSING
BRUSH WITH HER.
- YOUR LEGS
LOOK EXACTLY LIKE MINE,
AND I JUST SHAVED MINE.
- SO I'M THINKING OF
GETTING A MOTORCYCLE.
YEAH, I'M GONNA NEED
A LEATHER JACKET
FOR WHEN I'M ON MY HOG
AND NEED TO GO INTO
A CONTROLLED SLIDE.
- THERE'S MY LITTLE GIRL.
I'VE GOT GREAT NEWS.
DADDY HAS THE ENTIRE DAY OFF.
- BUT YOU HAVE EVERY DAY OFF.
YOU DON'T HAVE A JOB.
- WELL--I DON'T NEED MONEY
TO HANG OUT WITH MY DAUGHTER.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- WE'RE GOING SHOPPING.
- OH, NO, NO.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
- narrator:
THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL WAS STOPPED
ON HIS WAY TO WORK.
- GET IN.
- WHAT?
- IF YOU CARE
ABOUT YOUR BROTHER,
YOU'LL GET IN THIS CAR.
- WHICH BROTHER?
- GOB.
LET ME BE CLEARER.
TELL HIM ROLLO WANTS HIM
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO HIS LEGS.
[knocking]
- narrator:
MICHAEL WENT LOOKING FOR GOB.
- MOM.
- I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
I WANT YOU TO HELP ME BREAK UP
YOUR BROTHER AND HIS GIRLFRIEND.
WELL, I'M ALL FOR THAT.
WE'VE JUST GOTTA FIND HIM FIRST.
- HE'S LOCKED ON THE BALCONY.
- OH.
YOU MEANT BUSTER.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
TALKING ABOUT GOB.
- NO. I WILL NOT HAVE BUSTER
DATING MY BEST FRIEND.
- narrator:
TENSION HAD BEEN HIGH
BETWEEN THE TWO LUCILLES
SINCE BUSTER HAD ANNOUNCED
HE'D BEEN DATING HER.
ALTHOUGH NEITHER
HAD ADDRESSED THIS,
BOTH HAD GIVEN INDICATIONS
OF THEIR TRUE FEELINGS.
- MOM, YOU'RE RUINING OUR FORT.
- I MEAN, SHE'S BEEN
A FAMILY FRIEND FOR YEARS.
IT'S JUST...CREEPY.
HI, BUDDY.
MOM, I THINK
YOU MIGHT BE OVERREACTING.
- SHE CHANGED HIM
AS A BABY.
- OKAY. THAT-THAT'S
ABOUT THE CREEPIEST THING
I'VE EVER HEARD.
- THAT'S WHY
SHE DIDN'T LOOK SURPRISED.
- YOU'RE THE ONLY CHILD
WHO CHOSE A SPOUSE I LIKED,
AND SHE'S THE ONE
WHO HAD TO DIE.
- I KNOW.
THAT'S ROUGH FOR YOU.
MOM, I'M LOOKING FOR GOB.
THERE'S
SOME PEOPLE AFTER HIM,
AND I DON'T KNOW
WHETHER IT'S GAMBLING OR WHAT,
BUT, UM,
THEY WANNA BREAK HIS LEGS.
- IT'S A GOOD THING
HE'S ALREADY GOT
THAT LITTLE SCOOTER.
[laughs]
OH, DON'T GIVE ME
THAT LOOK.
I HAPPEN TO BE
A MORE CARING MOTHER THAN MOST.
- WHERE'S MY BED?
- I PUT IT IN STORAGE.
I GUESS YOU'LL JUST
HAVE TO DECIDE
WHICH LUCILLE YOU WANT TO
SPEND YOUR NIGHTS WITH.
- OKAY, BEFORE
I LEAVE THIS PLACE
FOR THE LAST TIME EVER,
HAS ANYONE SEEN GOB?
- I SAW HIM LAST NIGHT
AT THE PLAYTIME PIZZA THEATER,
ON MY DATE.
OF WHICH I HAVE
ANOTHER ONE TONIGHT.
AND I'M GOING TO
CONTINUE DATING, MOM.
- SOUNDS A LITTLE BIT LIKE
"DATING MOM."
- IT'S STARTING TO FEEL
A LITTLE LIKE IT.
- HMM.
- narrator:
LUCILLE DECIDED
SHE NEEDED
THE HELP OF BUSTER'S FATHER.
UNFORTUNATELY,
AFTER A RECENT ESCAPE ATTEMPT,
GEORGE SR. HAD BEEN
PUT IN SOLITARY CONFINEMENT.
MICHAEL WENT TO FIND HIS BROTHER
AT HIS LATEST GIG.
- WHAT'S UP, MIKE?
- YEAH. WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
- CAN'T GET ANY WORK, MIKE.
MAGICIANS' ALLIANCE
HAS BLACKBALLED ME
FROM EVERY VENUE IN TOWN.
- HMM.
- EVEN MY OWN
SO- CALLED GIRLFRIEND
DOESN'T BELIEVE IN ME.
- WELL, I DON'T WANNA GET INTO
THAT PART OF YOUR LIFE ANYMORE.
OKAY, LISTEN,
I JUST CAME HERE TO TELL YOU
THAT THIS GUY NAMED ROLLO
PULLED ME OVER
AND MADE SOME THREATS.
- WHAT KIND OF THREATS?
HE SAID TO SAY GOOD-BYE
TO YOUR LEGS.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER
THIS GUY'S A MOBSTER,
A LOAN SHARK,
SOMETHING EQUALLY SCARY.
- MAGICIAN.
- I THINK YOU'RE CONFUSING SCARY
WITH SILLY.
THIS GUY WAS FRIGHTENING.
HE WAS IN A LIMO.
- NO, HE'S A MAGICIAN.
HE REPLACED ME IN THE ALLIANCE.
HE'S THE REASON I GOTTA
DO MY ACT IN THIS HELLHOLE.
- WHY DOES HE WANNA
BREAK YOUR LEGS?
- HE DOESN'T WANT TO
BREAK MY LEGS.
HE WANTS TO TAKE MY LEGS.
- I-I DON'T--
- THE LEGS, THE BOTTOM HALF OF
MY SAW-THE-LADY-IN-HALF TRICK.
NO, NOT NOW.
I'M SHOWING HIM
HOW TO DO THE TRICK.
TWO CHICKS CURL UP IN A BOX.
WE CALL ONE THE HEAD
AND ONE THE LEGS.
- SO THAT'S HOW THEY DO IT.
- GOD, I GOTTA STOP
GIVING THESE THINGS AWAY.
- THE TOP HALF THERE,
WHAT DO YOU DO ABOUT THAT?
- I JUST GET A VOLUNTEER
FROM THE CROWD.
- OH, YEAH?
- THE OLD TOP HALF QUIT
WHEN SHE FOUND OUT
I WAS SLEEPING WITH THE LEGS.
- I GUESS WORD
REALLY GETS AROUND IN THERE.
SO ROLLO WANTS YOUR LEGS,
BUT YOU'RE CHEATING ON MARTA
WITH THOSE LEGS.
- WOULD YOU GIVE ME
A BREAK, PLEASE?
THE LEGS ARE INSANELY JEALOUS.
- IS THAT WHY YOU HAVEN'T SEEN
MARTA FOR THE PAST FEW DAYS?
THIS IS ALL ABOUT
YOUR LOVE LIFE AGAIN, ISN'T IT?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
JUST FORGET IT.
I CAME HERE
TO TRY TO HELP YOU.
- HEY, I APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
- GREAT. GREAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT, GOB?
MARTA IS A
ONCE-IN-A-LIFETIME WOMAN.
SHE'S A TREASURE.
AND I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE SHOWING HER
ENOUGH RESPECT, OKAY?
- SHE DOESN'T RESPECT
MY CAREER.
- OKAY.
- HE'S HAVING SEX
WITH A WOMAN IN HIS ACT?
- I GOTTA TELL MARTA
WHAT'S GOING ON.
- FIRST OF ALL,
SHE'LL HATE YOU FOR IT.
IT'S CALLED SHOOT THE MESSENGER.
SECONDLY,
IT'S NOT IN YOUR NATURE.
I MEAN,
YOU'RE LIKE MR. MORALS.
YOU CAN'T EVEN
TAKE A DESK CHAIR.
- DAMN IT.
I-I'M A SAINT, YOU KNOW?
I'M A LIVING SAINT,
AND I GET
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING OUT OF IT.
- WELL, YOU GET A FALSE FEELING
OF SUPERIORITY.
- I KNOW.
THAT IS NICE, BUT THIS TIME,
IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
WHY DO I ALWAYS
HAVE TO BE THE ONE
THAT HAS TO SET
THE GOOD EXAMPLE FOR EVERYONE?
- HEY, GUYS.
- OH, THAT'S WHY.
- HEY, MOM.
- HEY, HONEY.
- MOO?
- MMM.
MOO, HONEY.
- YOU HAVE TO BE SOME SORT OF
SHE-HULK TO GET THIS.
- YOU JUST GOTTA
REALLY DIG.
- WELL, IT'S NOT--
ENJOY--
OH, MAEBY, GREAT NEWS.
I GOT MY HANDS ON SOME MONEY.
I CAN'T SAY HOW OR WHEN--
OR WHERE MY WEDDING RING IS,
BUT MY PURSE OVERFLOWETH
AS DO MY HIGH SPIRITS,
SO A-SHOPPING WE MUST GO.
- DAD, WE ALREADY WENT.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE WEARING
ALL THIS LEATHER.
I'M REALLY INTO LEATHER.
TELL MOM.
- YES.
- IF YOU EVER NEED
TO BORROW ANY MONEY OR--
- NO.
THANK YOU, NO.
- narrator: SO TOBIAS
CHOSE TO PURSUE
A COMMON INTEREST
WITH HIS DAUGHTER.
- MAY I HELP YOU?
- I HOPE SO.
I'M LOOKING
FOR SOMETHING THAT SAYS,
"DAD LIKES LEATHER."
- SOMETHING THAT SAYS,
"LEATHER DADDY?"
- OH, IS THERE SUCH A THING?
- narrator: LATER THAT DAY,
MICHAEL GOT A SURPRISE VISIT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I WAS LOOKING FOR GOB.
HE SAID HE WAS
WORKING HERE TODAY.
- OH, YES?
PLEASE.
HE SAID THAT, HUH?
HE SAID THAT HE'S WORKING, HUH?
WOW. HERE?
WHAT ELSE DID HE SAY?
DID HE TELL YOU
THAT I GAVE HIM YOUR MESSAGE?
NOT THAT I'M THE MESSENGER,
YOU KNOW?
- HE TOLD ME.
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU SAID TO HIM,
BUT IT REALLY
TURNED HIM AROUND.
- HE SAID I WAS A TREASURE.
- SHE'S A TREASURE.
- AND A
ONCE-IN-A-LIFETIME WOMAN.
- MM-HMM.
LISTEN, MARTA, GOB IS--A POET.
- MM.
- HE'S TOUCHED.
I'M GONNA TELL HIM
THAT YOU STOPPED BY,
AND, UH,
YOU HAVE A NICE DAY.
- THANK YOU.
YOU'RE SUCH A GOOD BROTHER.
ALWAYS TRYING TO HELP HIM.
OH, AND HE SHOWED ME
THE WATCH YOU GAVE HIM.
- THE WATCH?
- I APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
- narrator: AND SO,
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
MICHAEL SET A PLAN IN MOTION
TO TAKE SOMETHING
THAT DIDN'T BELONG TO HIM.
- YOU KNOW,
I WAS THINKING,
I'D LIKE TO HELP YOU GUYS OUT
ONE MORE TIME.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU SHOULD DO?
YOU SHOULD SURPRISE GOB ONSTAGE.
I KNOW THAT HE'S LOOKING
FOR A NEW ASSISTANT.
- REALLY?
- MM-HMM.
- COULD YOU HELP ME
WITH THAT?
- YES.
- YOU REALLY ARE
A GOOD GUY, MICHAEL.
- WELL, YOU CAN'T CHANGE
WHO YOU ARE.
- [singing]
START SHOPPING BY FINGERS
WE'RE LIVING IN
YOUR WORLD NOW THIS TIME
- narrator: MICHAEL WENT TO
THE POPULAR MAGIC PARLOR,
THE GOTHIC CASTLE,
TO ASK A FAVOR OF ROLLO.
I WAS WONDERING IF, UH--
IF YOU WOULD
GIVE MY BROTHER A SHOW?
ONE MORE CHANCE TO GET BACK IN
WITH THE ALLIANCE.
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
AND--AND YOU WILL GET
YOUR LEGS BACK.
- HOW?
- YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO REVEAL MY TRICK?
- narrator: SO MICHAEL
WENT TO GIVE HIS BROTHER
THE GOOD NEWS.
- REALLY, TOMORROW NIGHT?
- YEAH. YOU JUST GOTTA MAKE SURE
YOU DO THE SAWING IN HALF TRICK.
- I DON'T EVEN HAVE
A TOP HALF.
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
I GOT SOMEONE I WANT YOU TO USE.
SHE'S PERFECT, A GREAT GIRL.
YOU'RE ACTUALLY
DOING ME A FAVOR.
- HAS SHE GOT BIG CANS?
- I'LL SEE YA THERE, GOB.
- YOU'RE A GOOD BROTHER.
- YOU'RE A HORRIBLE BROTHER,
MICHAEL.
- PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
- YOU'RE GONNA PUT MARTA
ONSTAGE WITH THE LEGS?
- IT'S GONNA BLOW UP.
LEGS GET UPSET.
MARTA GETS UPSET.
MARTA LEAVES GOB,
AND I DON'T GET SHOT.
- YOU'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO PULL THE TRIGGER ON THIS.
YOU CAN'T ESCAPE IT, MICHAEL.
YOU'RE THE GOOD GUY.
- CALL ME WHAT YOU WANT.
- AN IMPOTENT MAN-BOY?
- BUT IT IS DONE.
THE PLAN IS IN MOTION.
- THIS JUST ISN'T YOU.
- IT'S ME NOW.
IT'S THE ME THAT CAN RECLINE.
thump!
- DID THAT HURT?
- NO.
- THIS STUFF'S KIND OF HOT,
ISN'T IT?
- I HADN'T NOTICED.
- HEY, GANG.
MIND IF SQUEEZE IN HERE
FOR A MOMENT?
OH!
LOOK AT US.
WHO'D WANNA MESS
WITH ANY OF US, HUH?
- EXCUSE ME.
- YES. OOP.
- DID YOU GET A JOB
OR SOMETHING?
- NO, NO, I DIDN'T.
UNLESS YOU CONSIDER
"WORLD'S COOLEST DADDY" A JOB.
IF I--
[chokes and grunts]
- HEY, DAD.
- HEY, BUDDY.
YOU'RE STILL
WEARING THAT JACKET, HUH?
- YEAH. I WAS JUST
GOING FOR A NEW LOOK.
- YEAH?
- TRYING TO INTRODUCE
SOME EDGE TO THE WHOLE PALETTE.
- HMM, KIND OF LIKED YOU
THE WAY YOU WERE.
- YOU DID?
- YEAH, I MEAN,
WE CAN'T REALLY
CHANGE WHO WE ARE ANYWAY,
RIGHT?
- WISH YOU'D TOLD ME THAT
BEFORE I THREW AWAY
MY WINDBREAKER.
OH, YOU BOUGHT A CHAIR.
- UH, NO, ACTUALLY,
I BORROWED IT.
LIKE WE TALKED ABOUT.
- WELL, I THOUGHT WE DECIDED
THAT WAS LIKE STEALING.
- IS THAT WHERE WE LANDED
ON THAT?
- narrator: AS MICHAEL
WAS BECOMING MORE SELFISH,
HIS FATHER WAS CHOOSING
A MORE PIOUS PATH.
WHICH MADE
BUSTER AND LUCILLE'S VISIT
GO MUCH DIFFERENTLY
THAN PLANNED.
- WHY IS THERE
A PIECE OF SHOE ON YOUR HEAD?
- THIS IS A--
WELL, IT'S A REMINDER
THAT THE DIVINE PRESENCE
IS ALWAYS ABOVE ME.
- WELL, MORE IMPORTANTLY,
BUSTER'S BEEN HUMPING
THE WIDOW AUSTERO.
- MOM.
- IS THAT TRUE?
- NO. WE'RE TAKING IT SLOW.
- HE STAYS THERE SOMETIMES
UNTIL 7:00, 8:00 AT NIGHT.
PEANUT BRITTLE ON HIS BREATH.
IS SHE THE ONE WHO'S GOING TO
TAKE HIM TO THE DENTIST?
- SHE ALREADY HAS.
- [gasps]
- [sighs]
[speaking Yiddish]
- WHAT?
- "MAY YOU LIVE.
MAY YOU BE WELL.
I GIVE YOU MY BLESSING."
- WOW! REALLY?
- ARE YOU
OUT OF YOUR MIND?
- JUST FOLLOW THE HEART
THAT GOD GAVE YOU, HMM?
- NO TOUCHING.
NO--
[clears throat]
- CAN YOU GET ME
SOME OF THAT PEANUT BRITTLE?
- narrator:
ON THE NIGHT OF THE SHOW,
THE FAMILY ARRIVED
AT THE GOTHIC CASTLE,
AND IN THE GREEN ROOM,
MICHAEL WAS PREPARING MARTA
FOR THE TRICK.
- AT THE BOTTOM OF THE BOX.
AND YOU TWO GUYS
ARE FREE TO TALK.
OKAY.
GOB, GOB, GOB.
- WHAT IS GOING ON?
WHERE'S THE TOP HALF?
I HAVE TO TEACH HER THIS TRICK.
SHE'S GOTTA FOLD HER KNEES.
- IT'S A FANTASTIC TRICK.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO WORRY, THOUGH.
I'VE ALREADY TOLD HER.
NOW, WHERE ARE THE LEGS?
ARE THEY RUNNING LATE?
- SO IS EVERYONE HERE?
- I THINK SO.
I HAVEN'T SEEN TOBIAS.
- narrator: IN FACT,
TOBIAS HAD INTENDED TO COME,
BUT HAD A SLIGHT
MISCOMMUNICATION
WITH HIS CABDRIVER.
- WHERE TO, MATE?
- THE GOTHIC CASTLE.
- GOTHIC ASSHOLE?
- THAT'S WHAT I SAID.
- narrator: AND ENDED UP
IN THE WRONG LOCATION.
[club music pounding]
- OH, I AM GLAD
I DIDN'T GO WITH THAT OUTFIT.
YES, HELLO.
I AM LOOKING FOR THE MAGIC.
DANKE SCHOEN.
- OH.
HELLO, LUCILLE.
- HELLO, LUCILLE.
HAVING A GOOD TIME
WITH MY SON?
- ACTUALLY, WE'RE HAVING
A WONDERFUL TIME.
- YOU KNOW,
HE'S DAMAGED GOODS.
HE WAS BORN WITH
A HOLE IN HIS HEART.
- NOW,
LISTEN TO ME, LUCILLE.
I'M GONNA FILL THAT HOLE,
'CAUSE WE'RE IN LOVE.
- OH, PLEASE.
YOU'RE NO MORE
IN LOVE WITH HIM THAN I AM.
- OKAY, WE'RE ALL
SAYING SOME THINGS
WE'RE GOING TO REGRET.
- narrator: MEANWHILE,
GOB WAS ALMOST READY
TO BEGIN HIS SHOW.
- OKAY.
IT'S MAGIC TIME.
- HEY, GOOD LUCK OUT THERE NOW.
- HEY, LISTEN,
I GOT YOU SOMETHING
FOR BEING SUCH A GOOD GUY,
NOT THAT IT'S A SURPRISE,
YOU ALWAYS ARE.
- OH, WELL, UH--
MY WATCH.
- I WANT YOU TO HAVE IT.
- WELL, YOU'VE STOLEN
SO MANY THINGS FROM ME
OVER THE YEARS.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
YOU'VE EVER
GIVEN SOMETHING BACK.
I WANNA TRY TO BE
A BETTER BROTHER,
LIKE YOU ARE TO ME.
- WE'RE READY FOR YOU.
- GOB...
HAVE A GOOD SHOW
OUT THERE.
[Europe's "The Final Countdown"
plays]
- LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
A MAGICIAN NAMED GOB.
[music grows louder]
- DAD?
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHERE'S THE LEATHER JACKET?
- IT'S LIKE YOU SAID,
YOU CAN'T CHANGE WHO YOU ARE.
SO WHAT?
SO I DON'T HAVE ANY HAIR
ON MY ARMS OR LEGS.
SO WHAT?
YOU KNOW, A LEATHER JACKET'S
NOT GONNA CHANGE THAT.
YOU KNOW, I WAS TRYING
TO ACT LIKE A TOUGH GUY,
AND IT'S WRONG.
I'M JUST A BORING,
OLD NICE GUY LIKE YOU.
- I'M NOT THAT NICE.
- DAD, IF THIS
IS ABOUT THE CHAIR,
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
YOU DESERVE IT.
YOU KNOW, IT'S NOT LIKE
YOU'D EVER STEAL SOMETHING BIG.
- narrator: MICHAEL
WAS HAVING SECOND THOUGHTS
ABOUT HIS PLAN,
BUT THEN HE GOT
SOME UNEXPECTED HELP.
- HEY, I'M SORRY TO INTERRUPT.
YOU'D BETTER TELL GOB,
THE LEGS AREN'T COMING.
- OH, MY GOD.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE THE LEGS
WOULD SCREW HIM LIKE THIS.
THIS IS HIS ONE LAST CHANCE.
THEY'LL NEVER
LET HIM IN THE ALLIANCE AGAIN.
YOU HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.
THIS IS SO IMPORTANT
TO ME AND GOB.
- WHERE AM I GONNA GET A PAIR
OF BEAUTIFUL WOMEN'S LEGS
ON SUCH SHORT NOTICE?
- narrator: SO THE TRICK
WENT FORWARD AS PLANNED.
- AND NOW, MY HOPEFULLY LOVELY
ASSISTANT WILL JOIN ME.
[applause]
- OH!
- WIGGLE THOSE
SEXY GAMS, LADY.
- I'M OKAY WITH MYSELF.
I'M OKAY WITH MYSELF.
- [giggles]
- MOM, DID YOU SEE IT?
I'M BACK IN.
I'VE GOT THE CAREER BACK.
HANK YOU FOR COMING.
- narrator:
AND WHEN LUCILLE NOTICED
HOW HAPPY MARTA HAD MADE GOB,
SHE REALIZED HOW IMPORTANT
LOVE WAS TO HER CHILDREN.
- MOM.
- HELLO, BUSTER.
- IF YOU'RE STILL MAD,
I DON'T CARE.
I'M IN LOVE.
- I ACTUALLY CAME TO ASK
LUCILLE SOMETHING.
- WHAT?
- I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU'D LIKE TO PLAY BRIDGE
WITH ME NEXT WEEK?
- OH, I'D ABSOLUTELY ADORE IT.
OH, LUCILLE.
OH, GOD.
LOOK AT US, BUSTER.
WE'RE BACK TOGETHER AGAIN:
LUCILLE AND LUCILLE.
- YOU GUYS ARE FRIENDS AGAIN.
YOU CAN PLAY BRIDGE TOGETHER.
[kissing noise
and Buster yelling]
COULD YOU JUST--
JUST SEPARATE?
[loud cough]
- narrator: MICHAEL WATCHED
AS THE BROTHER
HE SWORE TO STOP HELPING
ENJOYED THE GIRLFRIEND
HE HELPED HIM REUNITE WITH.
AND SO HE RETURNED TO WORK,
ACCEPTING THE FACT
THAT HE WAS A GOOD GUY
BUT NOT AS GOOD
AS EVERYONE THOUGHT.
- THIS REALLY WORKED BETTER
WITH THE CHAIR.
- narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
THE ALLIANCE DECIDES
TO LET GOB BACK IN.
- TELL ME,
HOW DID YOU GET
TWO ALLIANCE-APPROVED ASSISTANTS
WITH SUCH SHORT NOTICE?
- OH, THAT WAS JUST
MY GIRLFRIEND AND MY NEPHEW.
[murmuring ]
- WELL, YOU'RE OUT.
- narrator: AND TOBIAS
GETS SOME GOOD NEWS.
- I GOT A GIG.
- [singing] THERE'S WHERE
MY HEART IS TURNING EVER
THERE'S WHERE
THE OLD FOLKS STAY
[whip cracks]