narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
narrator: MICHAEL BLUTH
WAS TALKING TO HIS SON
ABOUT HIS LATEST TEST.
- A-MINUS, HUH?
- PROUD OF ME?
- VERY PROUD
MINUS.
BETTER GO HIT THE BOOKS AGAIN.
GET UP THERE.
- C-MINUS.
"C" M-I-N-E-S.
- DID YOU EVEN STUDY?
- NO, I DIDN'T.
- WOW.
HOW IMPRESSIVE IS THAT?
- WELL, THE BAR
FOR THE REFRIGERATOR
HAS BEEN LOWERED, HUH?
- OH, GRADES ARE MEANINGLESS.
MAEBY'S LAST SCHOOL DIDN'T
EVEN HAVE THEM.
narrator: BACK IN BOSTON,
MAEBY'S PARENTS HAD ENROLLED HER
IN A PROGRESSIVE SCHOOL
WITH ITS OWN SYSTEM
OF EVALUATION.
- ALL I'M SAYING, LINDSAY,
IS THAT, YOU KNOW, YOU MIGHT
WANT TO PUSH HER A LITTLE BIT.
BECAUSE A KID WITHOUT DISCIPLINE
CAN GET INTO SOME
PRETTY TOUGH STUFF.
- SO YOU THINK SHE'S GONNA
SUDDENLY TURN TO DRUGS
'CAUSE SHE GOT A C-PLUS?
- MINUS. AND, YES, I THINK
THAT, WITHOUT BOUNDARIES,
A KID CAN GET INTO TROUBLE.
AND YES, SOMETIMES
THAT COULD MEAN DRUGS.
- WELL, I THINK STRESS
IS WHAT LEADS TO TROUBLE,
YOU KNOW THE KIND YOU PUT
ON GEORGE MICHAEL,
EVEN WHEN HE GETS AN "A."
- MINUS.
AND AN "A" GETS HIM ICE CREAM.
HE KNOWS THAT.
- SEE, YOU'RE AS BAD AS DAD
WITH HIS RIDICULOUS LESSONS.
narrator: GEORGE SR. HAD
USED HIS CONSIDERABLE MEANS
TO STAGE INTRICATE SCENARIOS
TO TEACH HIS CHILDREN
WHAT HE CONSIDERED
VALUABLE LIFE LESSONS.
- I NEED HELP.
- I'LL GET MY GEAR.
narrator: TYPICALLY, THESE
SCENARIOS WOULD INVOLVE A MAN
NAMED J. WALTER WEATHERMAN,
A ONE-TIME EMPLOYEE
WHO LOST HIS ARM
IN A BLUTH COMPANY
CONSTRUCTION ACCIDENT.
[whimpers]
- WHY ARE YOU HITTING YOURSELF?
WHY ARE YOU HITTING YOURSELF?
- WE'RE OUT OF MILK.
I COULD HAVE GOT IT EARLIER
IF SOMEONE WOULD HAVE
LEFT A NOTE.
[tires screech]
OH.
[grunts]
[all screaming]
- WHY? IF SOMEONE
HAD LEFT A NOTE,
THIS-THIS INNOCENT MAN
WOULD STILL HAVE HIS ARM.
WHY?
[screaming continues]
- AND THAT'S WHY
YOU ALWAYS LEAVE A NOTE.
- WELL, THOSE LESSONS WORKED,
DIDN'T THEY?
I MEAN, WE STILL
LEAVE NOTES TO THIS DAY.
- OH, THAT'S WHAT
THAT WAS ABOUT.
I THOUGHT HE WAS TRYING
TO GET US OFF DAIRY.
- I NEED A FAVOR.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO,
"HELLO. I NEED A FAVOR"?
- I OWE HOT COPS 500 BUCKS.
- "HOT COPS"?
- IT'S THE STRIPPING AGENCY
I USED TO WORK FOR.
COP UNIFORM.
- RIGHT.
- YOU KNOW, I MIGHT HAVE BEEN
JUST A LITTLE TOO BELIEVABLE.
[disco music]
[pounding]
POLICE! OPEN UP!
[shotgun blast]
ANYWAY, THEY'RE CLAIMING THAT I
NEVER DELIVERED ON THE GIG.
- I'M NOT AN A.T.M.
- MICHAEL, I KEEP FORGETTING
HOW HILARIOUS YOU ARE.
- SHH, SHH, SHH.
YOU'RE MAKING IT WORSE.
- AM I?
- TELL YOU WHAT.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU THE CASH,
BUT IN RETURN, I GET TO
ASK YOU FOR A FAVOR SOMETIME.
- MY GUT IS TELLING ME "NO,"
BUT MY GUT IS ALSO VERY HUNGRY.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL DO IT.
narrator: MICHAEL THEN LEFT
FOR HIS MOTHER'S APARTMENT,
WHERE SHE GREETED HIM WITH
SOME NOT-SO-SURPRISING NEWS.
- I NEED A FAVOR.
- WE OUGHT TO PUT THAT
ON OUR FAMILY CREST.
- [laughing]
OH, MICHAEL--
- SPARE ME.
- THE S.E.C. IS MAKING ME
INVENTORY EVERYTHING I OWN.
THEY WANT ME TO PROVE
NO NEW PURCHASES HAVE BEEN MADE
WITH COMPANY MONEY.
- AND THERE HAVEN'T BEEN, RIGHT?
- NOT AFTER WE DOCTOR
ALL THESE RECEIPTS.
- I CAN'T HELP YOU, MOM.
I'VE GOT A JOB.
I GOTTA MAKE SOME MONEY,
SO YOU CAN BUY MORE THINGS
AND DESTROY THE EVIDENCE.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'LL ASK LINDSAY.
[door closes]
- HEY, BUSTER.
- HEY, BROTHER.
- YOU HEADED OVER
TO YOUR GIRLFRIEND'S?
- YEAH. SHE'S DOWN AGAIN.
narrator: BUSTER'S
GIRLFRIEND, LUCILLE AUSTERO,
SUFFERS FROM CHRONIC VERTIGO,
WHICH SHE HAS BEEN
TRYING TO FIGHT
WITHOUT THE USE OF MEDICATION.
- AND HER NAUSEA'S
GOTTEN REALLY BAD TOO.
IT'S REALLY BEEN
DIFFICULT ON US.
IT'S DEFINITELY
TAKING ITS TOLL.
- WELL, YOU KNOW
YOU'RE FREE TO GO, PAL.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU MADE
A COMMITMENT TO THIS WOMAN.
- WELL, I DIDN'T MAKE
A "COMMITMENT."
I DID REFER TO IT
AS OUR NAUSEA.
- MM.
- BUT YOU KNOW,
THAT'S WHEN WE WERE GOIN' AT IT
REALLY HOT AND HEAVY.
- WELL, NOW IT'S MY NAUSEA.
narrator: LATER, LUCILLE
STOPPED BY THE MODEL HOME
TO ENLIST HER DAUGHTER'S HELP
CATALOGING HER VALUABLES.
- I CAN'T.
- WHY NOT?
BECAUSE I'M--
DON'T WANT TO.
WELL, MAYBE I DON'T FEEL
LIKE BEING CRITICIZED
AROUND THE CLOCK.
- I DON'T CRITICIZE YOU.
AND IF YOU'RE WORRIED
ABOUT CRITICISM,
SOMETIMES A DIET
IS THE BEST DEFENSE.
- OH, HEY, GANGY.
- HI.
- D-PLUS.
SIGN THIS.
- THIS IS A D-MINUS.
- WELL, EITHER WAY,
IT'S ABOVE A "D," RIGHT?
- ANOTHER WORLD-BEATER.
narrator:
AND LINDSAY REALIZED
SHE NEEDED TO TAKE A FIRMER HAND
WITH HER DAUGHTER.
- I'M NOT SIGNING THIS.
- FINE. I WILL.
IS "LINDSAY"
WITH AN "A" OR AN "E"?
- OKAY, LOOK, I KNOW YOU GOT
A "CROCODILE" IN SPELLING,
BUT THIS HAS GONE TOO FAR.
I HATE TO SAY IT,
BUT MICHAEL MIGHT BE RIGHT.
YOU NEED TO LEARN
A LITTLE DISCIPLINE.
- HMM.
NOPE, THAT DOESN'T FEEL RIGHT.
- NO, NO, NO.
I'M TELLING YOU.
YOU ARE NOW PUNISHED.
I PUNISH THEE.
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WHAT COULD YOU
POSSIBLY COME UP WITH
THAT WOULD PUNISH ME?
- OH, I HAVE TO COME UP
WITH ANOTHER THING?
- OH, LINDSAY, BEFORE I GO,
I JUST HAVE ONE WORD FOR YOU.
"SLEEVES."
- YOU'RE GOING TO SPEND THE DAY
WORKING FOR YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
- NO. NO, THAT'S NOT THE ANSWER,
BECAUSE YOU--
WHAT? NO! YOU STUPID JERK!
WHY DON'T--
DUMB. DUMB.
DUMB, GEORGE MICHAEL.
DUMB, DUMB.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
CALM DOWN, YOU TWO.
IT'S JUST A MATH PROBLEM.
- YEAH, BUT IF I FAIL MATH,
THERE GOES MY CHANCE
AT A GOOD JOB AND A HAPPY LIFE
FULL OF HARD WORK,
LIKE YOU ALWAYS SAY.
- [sighs]
MAYBE I'M PUSHING YOU TOO HARD.
YOU'RE ALL STRESSED OUT.
YOUR EYES ARE ALL RED.
WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE THE NIGHT OFF.
JUST SHUT THE BOOK.
GO AHEAD.
JUST CLOSE THE BOOK.
YOUR FINGER
IS STILL IN THE BOOK.
GEORGE MICHAEL.
narrator: BUSTER, MEANWHILE, WAS
STILL WORRIED ABOUT LUCILLE 2,
WHOSE CONDITION
SEEMED TO BE WORSENING.
- YOU OKAY?
HOW'S YOUR NAUSEA?
- [moaning]
"OUR."
-  I MEAN, OUR--
OUR NAUSEA.
narrator: HE REMEMBERED A STUDY
HE TOOK PART IN
ON MEDICAL MARIJUANA
AND ITS EFFECTS ON NAUSEA.
THE SUBJECT TOOK THE DRUG
IN THE FORM OF A T.H.C. PILL.
NAUSEA WAS THEN INDUCED
WITH A DAY AT THE CARNIVAL,
WHICH IS WHAT ATTRACTED
BUSTER TO THE EXPERIMENT
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
BUSTER WAS FOUND
TWO DAYS LATER
TRYING TO EAT HIS WAY THROUGH
THIS ENORMOUS PLASTER DONUT.
SO BUSTER WENT TO THE TOUGHEST,
MOST STREETWISE KID HE KNEW.
- TELL YOUR FRIENDS.
- HEY, NEPHEW. I WAS LOOKING
FOR YOU AT YOUR HOME.
- OH, YEAH, DAD TOLD ME
TO TAKE THE DAY OFF,
SO I DECIDED TO COME INTO WORK.
- OH.
SO I THOUGHT MAYBE YOU COULD
HELP ME GET SOME WEED.
- [utensil clatters]
IT'S NOT FOR ME.
IT'S FOR LUCILLE 2,
MY GIRLFRIEND.
- SHE'S YOUR GIRLFRIEND?
DAD SAID YOU WERE HER NURSE.
- LOOK, SHE'S SICK.
THIS COULD HELP HER.
PILLFORM WOULD ACTUALLY
BE FANTASTIC
BECAUSE I COULD PUT IT ON A
LITTLE TEA BISCUIT,
AND I COULD JUST TELL HER
IT'S A MARSHMALLOW.
- LOOK, I HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE TO GET SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, OKAY?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK I WOULD?
- WELL, YOU WORK HERE.
THIS PLACE
IS POT CENTRAL, RIGHT?
narrator: IN THE '70s,
THE BOARDWALK WAS THE PLACE
TO BUY MARIJUANA
IN NEWPORT BEACH.
THE STAND SERVED
AS A CONVENIENT MEETING PLACE
BECAUSE OF
THE BANANA'S RESEMBLANCE
TO A YELLOW MARIJUANA CIGARETTE.
IT HAD EVEN INSPIRED A SONG.
- [singing] BIG YELLOW JOINT
THE BIG YELLOW JOINT
I'LL MEET YOU DOWN
AT THE BIG YELLOW JOINT
- LOOK, I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T HELP YOU, OKAY?
WHY DON'T YOU
JUST ASK UNCLE GOB?
- WHY ARE YOU HITTING YOURSELF?
WHY ARE YOU HITTING YOURSELF?
- NO. NO.
HE'D NEVER DO IT.
BESIDES, HE ALWAYS MAKES FUN OF
ME FOR DATING LUCILLE.
EVERYBODY DOES.
- THAT'S HORRIBLE.
- LOOK, MAYBE YOU COULD
TELL GOB FOR ME,
BUT YOU CAN'T TELL HIM
IT'S FOR ME.
YOU CAN'T TELL ANYBODY.
- I'M WORKING.
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
TO TAKE THE DAY OFF.
- YEAH, BUT THERE'S
NOTHING TO DO.
I MEAN, MAEBY'S AT GANGY'S.
- FIND SOMETHING TO DO.
GO MAKE MISTAKES,
GET IN TROUBLE--BE YOUNG.
- YES! I TOTALLY AGREE.
MAKE A MISTAKE.
- NOW HERE. HERE'S 20 BUCKS.
I WANT YOU TO CLOSE UP SHOP
AND GO CRAZY.
GO FIND YOURSELF SOMETHING
TO BUY THAT YOU DON'T NEED.
- ABSOLUTELY. HERE.
TAKE 225 FROM ME.
- [singing] BIG YELLOW JOINT
BIG YELLOW JOINT
I'LL MEET YOU DOWN
AT THE BIG YELLOW JOINT
narrator: MAEBY WAS WORKING
WITH HER GRANDMOTHER.
- AND THIS IS FROM
WHEN YOUR POP-POP YELLED OUT,
"OH, MELANIE,"
WHEN HE WAS MAKING LOVE
TO GANGY.
- THIS IS SO MUCH FUN.
I CAN'T BELIEVE MY MOM THOUGHT
BEING HERE
WOULD BE A PUNISHMENT.
- OH, SHE THINKS
I'M TOO CRITICAL.
THAT'S ANOTHER FAULT OF HERS.
[gasps]
AH, YES.
THE WEEK WE HAD
THE AU PAIR.
YOU KNOW, YOUR MOTHER
ALWAYS WANTED THIS BROOCH.
- REALLY?
- DO YOU WANT IT?
- I DO NOW.
THAT'LL SHOW HER
FOR TRYING TO PUNISH ME.
- OH. PRETTY.
IT'LL DISTRACT
FROM THE FRECKLES.
[seagulls squawking]
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
NERVOUSLY APPROACHED
THE FAMILY YACHT
GOB HAD BEEN STAYING ON.
- UNCLE GOB?
narrator: WHEN HE SAW
THE YACHT WAS EMPTY,
GEORGE MICHAEL--
AS HE'D BEEN TRAINED TO DO
SINCE CHILDHOOD--LEFT A NOTE.
BACK AT THE MODEL HOME,
GOB SHOWED MICHAEL THE NOTE
HE'D FOUND AT THE DOCK.
- NO. THIS CAN'T BE
FROM MY SON.
- WELL, IT IS HIS HANDWRITING.
PLUS HE LEFT ME $200.
$100.
100. I ACCIDENTALLY SAID 200.
I DON'T KNOW--
- THIS IS IMPOSSIBLE.
WHY WOULD HE DO THIS?
- I KNOW, YOU KNOW.
I WAS SHOCKED.
I MEAN, REALLY,
A HUNDRED DOLLARS.
YOU CAN'T GET GOOD WEED
FOR A HUNDRED BUCKS.
- [sighs]
- ANYWAY, HERE YOU GO.
NOW WE ARE EVEN ON YOU
PAYING OFF THAT HOT COPS THING.
MIGHT JUST BE A FEW STEMS,
BUT IT SHOULD BE--
- GET THAT THE HELL
OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
- MAYBE YOU SHOULD
SAVE THE LECTURES FOR YOUR SON,
IF HE CAN REMEMBER THEM.
- MAN, I SPEAK TO LINDSAY
ONE TIME
ABOUT HER STUPID
HIPPIE PARENTING,
AND I END UP WITH A HIPPIE.
- YEAH, IT DOES SEEM
PRETTY QUICK.
- FOR ALL I KNOW, THIS HAS
BEEN GOIN' ON FOREVER.
YOU KNOW, HE'S BEEN STRESSED,
HIS EYES HAVE BEEN RED,
HIS GRADES ARE DROPPING.
- HEARD ABOUT THE A-MINUS.
- I'M GONNA GO FIND OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON.
HEY, WHAT YOU DOIN'?
- NOTHING.
- NO? SO, LISTEN, YOUR, UH,
YOUR UNCLE GOB
SEEMS TO THINK THAT HE SAW YOU
DOWN AT THE DOCKS TODAY.
WAS THAT YOU?
- NO, NO.
MAYBE IT WAS
THE OTHER GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU KNOW THE SINGER-SONGWRITER.
- YEAH, THAT MAKES SENSE.
- YEAH.
- WHAT'D YOU DO
WITH THE, UM--
WITH THE MONEY BUSTER AND I GAVE
YOU TO GO HAVE FUN WITH?
- I PUT THAT
IN MY SAVINGS ACCOUNT.
- IS THAT RIGHT?
- YEAH. SAVE UP.
- OKAY.
THANKS FOR BEING HONEST.
- YEAH.
- HE'S LYING TO ME.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
WHERE THE HELL
IS THIS FAMILY'S MORALITY?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- WHAT--
- IT'S COLD OUT HERE.
[coughs]
- SO WHAT DO I DO NOW?
IF I CONFRONT HIM, HE'S JUST
GONNA LIE TO ME AGAIN.
SHOULD I YELL AT HIM?
- DIDN'T DAD TEACH US THAT
WE DON'T YELL IN THIS FAMILY?
[kids yelling]
- TELL ME BEFORE
YOU HIT THE GAS.
[yelling continues]
- I CAN'T HEAR YOU!
THE KIDS ARE YELLING.
- TELL ME BEFORE
YOU HIT THE GAS.
- I GUESS YOU'RE SAYING,
"HIT THE GAS."
[engine revs]
- DON'T! WAIT! NO!
[screams]
[kids screaming]
- THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T YELL.
- [laughing]
- YEAH, YELLING'S
NOT A GOOD WAY TO GO.
I GOT A BETTER IDEA.
[metal door slams]
- YOU WANNA TEACH
GEORGE MICHAEL A LESSON?
- YES, I DO,
AND IT'S GOTTA STICK.
HE'S GETTING INTO DRUGS, DAD,
AND HE'S LYING TO ME.
- THAT DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE THE BOY.
- I KNOW. I KNOW.
BUT IT'S MY FAULT.
I'VE BEEN PUSHING HIM TOO HARD.
IT'S JUST--
DUMB, DUMB. DUMB, MICHAEL.
- HEY, HEY.
- DUMB.
- SHH, SHH, SHH. I FORGIVE YOU.
- I DON'T WANT
YOUR FORGIVENESS, DAD.
I WANT THE GUY WITH THE ONE ARM
AND THE FAKE BLOOD.
J. WALTER WEATHERMAN--
HOW DO I GET AHOLD OF HIM?
- HE'S, UH, DEAD.
YOU KILLED HIM WHEN
YOU LEFT THE DOOR OPEN
WITH THE AIR CONDITIONER
RUNNING.
- FOR GOD'S SAKES, DAD.
HE'S NOT DEAD.
LISTEN, I NEED TO DO THIS SOON,
OKAY, LIKE, TONIGHT.
DOWN BY THE DOCKS--
I'M GONNA MAKE IT
LIKE A DRUG DEAL WENT BAD.
TONIGHT? NO. IT'S YONTIF.
IT'S THE FIRST NIGHT
OF YOM KIPPUR.
- DAD, THAT'S JUST--
THAT'S ONE NIGHT,
AND IT'S BACK IN SEPTEMBER.
THAT'S OKAY. YOU'VE ONLY BEEN A
JEW ABOUT TWO DAYS.
- JUST TRY TO TALK TO HIM.
- LIKE YOU TALKED TO ME
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP?
- I THOUGHT
YOU HATED THOSE LESSONS.
- I DID, BUT THEY WORKED.
AND THEY WILL WORK AGAIN.
- WELL, I'M DONE WITH THEM,
BECAUSE IT WAS WRONG, MICHAEL.
- COME ON.
- YOUR SON IS A TIMID,
THOUGHTFUL BOY.
HE'S A SCHOLAR,
LIKE HIS GRANDFATHER.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
OH, ALMOST SUNDOWN.
I HAVE TO PREPARE
FOR THE SABBATH.
- IT'S TUESDAY.
- SHH, SHH, SHH.
narrator: LINDSAY WENT TO SEE
HOW HER OWN ATTEMPT AT PARENTAL
DISCIPLINE WAS COMING ALONG.
- SO, HAVING FUN?
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT BROOCH?
- GANGY. NICE, HUH?
- THAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE FOR ME.
SHE WAS MY AU PAIR.
I'M THE ONE
WHO CLEARED MY THROAT
AND POINTED TO THE LAUNDRY ROOM.
MA! YOU KNOW I WANTED THAT.
- I KNOW,
BUT IT'S AN ELEPHANT,
AND I DIDN'T WANT
TO INVITE THE COMPARISON.
- NICE.
IN ANY EVENT,
YOUR PUNISHMENT IS OVER.
COME ON, MAEBY. LET'S GO.
- SHE'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
WE'RE HAVING FUN.
HERE, MAEBY.
TRY THIS ON.
- I SEE.
FINE. I WAS GONNA
TAKE HER OUT FOR ICE CREAM,
BUT IF YOU'D RATHER STAY HERE,
WELL, THAT'S JUST FINE WITH ME.
[door closes]
- WELL, WE COULD GO GET
SOME ICE CREAM, GANGY.
THAT WOULD BE FUN, RIGHT?
- I DON'T THINK SO.
THAT CHUBBY LITTLE WRIST
OF YOURS
IS TESTING THE TENSILE STRENGTH
OF THIS BRACELET AS IT IS.
narrator: MAEBY DECIDED
THAT PERHAPS SHE'D HAD ENOUGH
OF HER GRANDMOTHER.
- MAEBY.
MAEBY?
- HEY, GOB. IT'S MICHAEL.
LISTEN, I FIGURED OUT A WAY
FOR YOU TO REPAY THAT FAVOR.
DAD WOULDN'T HELP ME TEACH
GEORGE MICHAEL THE LESSON,
SO I NEED YOUR HELP
AND YOUR HOT COP FRIENDS.
I WANNA FAKE A DRUG BUST.
- MICHAEL, THESE GUYS
ARE REAL DANCERS.
THEY'VE NEVER DONE
ANY HOT POLICING.
- WELL, THEY DON'T
EVEN NEED TO BE HOT.
THEY JUST NEED TO SHOW UP
IN THOSE UNIFORMS.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL'S PLAN
WAS PUT INTO MOTION.
- WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
- WHAT?
- I AM LIKE
A CAGED ANIMAL.
MY OLD LADY'S
ON THE FLOOR, MAN.
I AM NOT S-ING AROUND.
- YEAH. GOB JUST CALLED.
HE'S GOT THE STUFF
AT THE YACHT.
- OH, GREAT. LET'S GO.
- NO, NO. I THINK MY DAD'S
ON TO THIS.
I'M OUT. I'M NOT--
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
COME ON.
GOB WILL NEVER
GIVE IT TO ME.
MY WOMAN IS SICK.
PLEASE?
narrator: LATER THAT NIGHT,
MICHAEL MADE THE FINAL
ARRANGEMENTS WITH GOB.
- ALL RIGHT, GOB, IS THIS
GONNA BE BELIEVABLE?
I WANT HIM SCARED.
I LOVE THIS KID.
- THESE GUYS ARE PROS,
MICHAEL.
THEY'RE GONNA
PUSH THE TENSION
TO THE LAST POSSIBLE MOMENT
BEFORE THEY STRIP.
- THEY'RE NOT GOING
TO STRIP, ARE THEY?
- I TOLD THEM NOT TO,
BUT I CAN'T PROMISE THAT
THEIR INSTINCTS WON'T KICK IN.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
- ANYWAY, TRUST ME.
IT'S GONNA BE TOTALLY REAL.
THIS KIND OF THING GOES ON
ALL THE TIME OUT HERE.
BOATS WAIT OFFSHORE,
LIGHTS ARE FLASHED.
A GUY COMES OVER
AND DROPS OFF A BAG.
IT'S GONNA FREAK
THE LITTLE BASTARD OUT.
narrator:
MICHAEL WENT OFF TO HIDE
WHILE BUSTER AND GEORGE MICHAEL
ARRIVED AS PLANNED.
- I REALLY APPRECIATE
YOU DOING THIS FOR ME.
YOU'RE MAKING A VERY
MISERABLE PERSON HAPPY.
- SHE REALLY FEELS AWFUL, HUH?
- OH. OH, I WAS TALKING
ABOUT ME.
BUT, YEAH, SHE'S A MESS.
BE CAREFUL.
- UNCLE GOB?
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
YOU WEREN'T FOLLOWED,
WERE YOU?
- NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
- ALL RIGHT, KID.
LET'S DEAL SOME DRUGS.
[switch clicking]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
- FLASHING THE LIGHTS--
SO THE DEALER KNOWS
WHAT'S GOIN' DOWN.
NOW WE WAIT.
- HOW LONG?
- WHO KNOWS?
HOUR.
MAYBE FIVE.
- DRUG DELIVERY!
YOU WANTED
SOME MARIJUANA?
- NO, NOT ME.
MY NEPHEW DID.
- [chuckles]
SHOW ME THE MONEY.
- SHOW US THE POT.
- I GOT IT RIGHT HERE.
- OH, MY GOD.
- NICE, RIGHT?
- OKAY, YOU CAN
PUT YOUR SHIRT DOWN, DEREK.
JUST GIVE HIM THE STUFF.
SO. WE HAVE A DEAL.
- WE HAVE A DEAL.
- HE'S RUINING HIS LIFE!
[dance music]
- POLICE OFFICERS! FREEZE!
- WHAT? OH, NO!
IT'S THE COPS!
AND A CONSTRUCTION WORKER.
- LET'S GET THIS PARTY STARTED.
- AREN'T YOU GUYS
GONNA CUFF HIM?
- YOU WANTED HANDCUFFS?
- ALL RIGHT. GEORGE MICHAEL,
HOPE YOU LEARNED
YOUR LESSON, PAL.
[Hot Cops cheering]
[continues]
[whooping, cheering]
- OKAY.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
[music stops]
- WHAT IS THIS?
- THIS IS A LESSON.
AND MAYBE I PUSHED YOU
INTO THIS,
BUT I LOVE YOU TOO MUCH
TO SEE YOU RUIN YOUR LIFE
WITH THAT CRAP.
- BUT IT WASN'T FOR ME.
- THEN WHO WAS IT FOR?
WHO? GIVE ME A NAME.
- OKAY, IT WAS FOR ME.
- YEAH.
- I WAS GONNA SMOKE THE
MARIJUANA LIKE A CIGARETTE.
- WELL, NOW YOU'RE LOOKING AT A
NICE BIG, FAT PUNISHMENT.
[footsteps running]
- I'M SORRY. EXCUSE ME.
I'M SORRY. OOH! UH--
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- THE, UH--THE BOY
WAS LOOKIN' OUT FOR ME.
- WHAT?
- IT-IT'S FOR MY GIRLFRIEND.
SHE'S SICK.
- WHY DON'T
YOU JUST WAIT IT OUT?
SHE'S GONNA BE GONE SOON.
[laughing]
- OH, THAT'S IT.
- HEY!
- WHY ARE YOU HITTING YOURSELF?
WHY ARE YOU HITTING YOURSELF?
- HEY! BUSTER!
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
EASY.
IS THAT TRUE?
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME THIS?
- WELL, YOU'RE ALWAYS TELLING ME
TO DO THE RIGHT THING--
PUT FAMILY FIRST.
- YOU KNOW, IT IS UNBELIEVABLE
THAT YOU'D ASK MY SON
TO SCORE YOU POT.
WHY DON'T YOU DRIVE HIM HOME,
AND YOU AND I WILL TALK
ABOUT THIS LATER.
GO AHEAD.
GO WITH BUSTER.
- I'M SORRY.
- HEY, WHAT ARE YOU GUYS DOIN'?
- WE GOT YOUR SIGNAL.
YOU FLASHED THE LIGHTS.
- WE GOT THE DRUGS.
YOU GOT THE MONEY?
- NO, NO. NO, NO, NO, NO.
WE'RE ALL GOOD.
- WE JUST WANT THE MONEY.
YOU WANNA MAKE THIS UGLY?
- WE WERE JUST TEACHING
THE YOUNG FELLOW A LESSON.
WE DON'T WANT
ANY TROUBLE WITH YOU.
- THANKS VERY MUCH.
- YOU KNOW WHO
YOU'RE DEALIN' WITH?
[siren wails]
- DROP THE BOXES!
PUT YOUR HANDS IN THE AIR.
- WHAT IS THIS?
- WE HAD NOTHIN'
TO DO WITH THIS!
- YOU SET US UP!
- NO, NO!
THESE ARE JUST STRIPPERS!
LOOK HOW HOT THEY ARE!
- EVERYBODY TAKE A BREATH!
[all shouting, indistinct]
[gunshots]
- OH, MY GOD! MY ARM!
- OH, MY GOD,
THIS GUY'S ARM...
JUST CAME OFF
AND LANDED ON THE DOCK.
narrator: MICHAEL REALIZED THAT
HIS FATHER HAD, ONCE AGAIN,
TAUGHT HIM
AN ELABORATE LESSON.
- AND THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T
TEACH LESSONS TO YOUR SON.
- HOW COULD YOU
DO THAT TO ME?
- I TOLD YOU HE'S A GOOD KID.
YOU SHOULD TRY TALKING TO HIM
WHEN YOU THINK HE'S IN TROUBLE.
DON'T MAKE THE SAME MISTAKE
I DID,
YOU KNOW--
TEACHING LESSONS.
- SO YOU TAUGHT ME A LESSON
NOT TO TEACH LESSONS?
- [sighs]
IT WAS MY LAST LESSON.
narrator:
BACK AT THE MODEL HOME.
- BACK FROM YOUR WONDERFUL TIME
WITH GANGY?
- WELL, ACTUALLY,
IT WASN'T SO WONDERFUL.
SHE CAN BE KINDA NASTY.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE MY MOM.
OH, UM,
I GOT YOU SOMETHING.
- YOU'RE GIVING ME THIS?
- YOU DESERVE IT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU HAD
TO PUT UP WITH HER
YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
- HONEY, THIS IS SO SWEET.
LET'S SELL IT
AND GO SHOPPING.
- YOU KNEW THE WHOLE TIME,
DIDN'T YOU?
- KIND OF.
ONE OF THE HOT COPS
IS MY CHOIR TEACHER.
-  BUDDY, I'M SORRY
ABOUT ALL THIS.
IT'S JUST, YOU KNOW, YOU WERE
SO STRESSED OUT,
AND I GUESS
I GOT SCARED AND--
I SHOULD PROBABLY LEARN TO TALK
WITH YOU A LITTLE BIT MORE, HUH?
- WELL, I THINK WE'RE OKAY.
- WE ARE, AREN'T WE?
I MEAN,
YOU KNOW THAT THERE'S NOTHING
THAT YOU CAN'T BE TOTALLY HONEST
WITH ME ABOUT.
I MEAN, YOU CAN SAY ANYTHING TO
ME, YOU KNOW, ANYTHING AT ALL.
- LIKE, SAY, I HAD A CRUSH
ON MY OWN COUSIN.
- HEY.
[snorts]
YOU JUST TAUGHT ME
A LESSON.
- [singing] BIG YELLOW JOINT
THE BIG YELLOW JOINT
- ALL RIGHT. WE'RE EVEN.
- [singing] I'LL MEET YOU DOWN
AT THE BIG YELLOW JOINT