male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING,
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL BLUTH
WAS TAKING HIS SON
TO AN INTERVIEW AT
THE PRESTIGIOUS MILFORD SCHOOL,
AN INSTITUTION
ONCE FAMOUS FOR ITS CREDO
THAT CHILDREN SHOULD BE
"NEITHER SEEN NOR HEARD."
- "WOMAN."
- [whispers]
THEY'RE NOT GETTING IN.
- BUT DAD, YOU KNOW,
I MIGHT NOT GET IN EITHER,
AND THAT WOULDN'T BE
THE END OF THE WORLD.
- SHH, WE'RE NOT EVEN GOING DOWN
THAT ROAD, OKAY?
THE NEXT FOUR YEARS
ARE ALL ABOUT YOUR FUTURE,
AND THAT'S THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING TO ME, OKAY?
- AND THINGS HAVE CHANGED
AROUND HERE.
WE HAVE TALKING SESSIONS
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
WE EVEN HAVE A TALKING ROOM
WHERE STUDENTS ARE ENCOURAGED
TO GO IN AND TALK
TO THEIR HEART'S CONTENT.
- SOUNDS LIKE FUN.
- FIRST THING HE'S SAID ALL DAY.
- THE POINT IS,
I'M NOT MY FATHER.
I DO THINK IT'S BEST
FOR THE MILFORD SCHOOL
TO DISTANCE ITSELF
FROM THE BLUTH NAME.
IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL.
- ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT THE FACT
THAT MY FATHER IS IN JAIL?
BECAUSE I DON'T LIKE TO BE
COMPARED TO MY FATHER EITHER.
- I DON'T MIND BEING
COMPARED TO MY FATHER.
- SAVE IT FOR
THE TALK ROOM, SON.
- SORRY.
- I CAN ASSURE YOU THAT
MY FAMILY IS BACK ON TRACK,
AND NO LONGER IN ANY TROUBLE.
- NOT ACCORDING
TO TODAY'S PAPER.
- OH, GOD.
WHAT HAVE WE DONE THIS TIME?
- DON'T EVER MENTION KLIMPY'S
TO ME AGAIN.
- WHAT DID YOU DO?
- IF I STILL HAD MONEY,
I'D BUY A KLIMPY'S
JUST TO BURN IT TO THE GROUND.
- I KNOW, MOM.
YOU HATE KLIMPY'S.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
- WELL, YOUR SISTER AND I TRIED
TO GET INTO
THAT NEW RESTAURANT, RUD,
AND THEY WOULDN'T LET US IN.
- MRS. BLUTH,
THERE'S ABSOLUTELY NO ROOM.
- COME ON.
I'VE SUDDENLY LOST MY APPETITE.
- OH, WHO'S GOING
TO BELIEVE THAT?
narrator: WITH HER BLOOD SUGAR
AT A PERILOUS LOW,
LUCILLE MADE LINDSAY PULL
INTO THE NEAREST RESTAURANT.
- WELCOME TO KLIMPY'S!
ANYWHERE YOU LIKE!
- THIS DOES NOT BODE WELL.
I'LL HAVE THE IKE
AND TINA TUNA.
- PLATE OR PLATTER?
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE QUESTION,
AND I WON'T RESPOND TO IT.
- AND WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
- I'D LIKE MY OLD LIFE BACK.
- SO THERE REALLY WAS NO FIGHT?
- WELL, ONE TINY THING
AT THE END.
- HOW CAN YOU TREAT ME THIS WAY?
- OH, PLEASE! EVERYTHING
I'VE SAID ABOUT YOU
CAN BE COVERED WITH MAKEUP AND
A LIE ABOUT A THYROID PROBLEM.
GOOD GRIEF ALMIGHTY!
YOU THINK I'M ENJOYING
MY SLIDE INTO POVERTY?
SORRY, LINDSAY.
THERE GOES YOUR DESSERT.
- WHY DON'T YOU EAT IT, MOTHER?
WHY DON'T YOU JUST TAKE
THIS CAKE AND SHOVE IT [bleep].
HEY, WHO CALLED THE COPS?
- IT WAS ALL JUST
A BIG MISUNDERSTANDING.
- TOTALLY BLOWN
OUT OF PROPORTION.
- WELL, LISTEN,
JUST THAT YOU KNOW,
I THINK IT COST GEORGE MICHAEL
A CHANCE TO GO
TO THE MILFORD SCHOOL.
- OH, BIG DEAL.
BUSTER'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO EVER LIKED IT.
narrator: BUSTER SO EXCELLED AT
BEING NEITHER SEEN NOR HEARD
THAT HE REMAINED
AT THE SCHOOL UNDETECTED
FOR A FULL TWO SEMESTERS AFTER
HE WAS SUPPOSED TO GRADUATE.
- NONETHELESS, MOTHER, I THINK
THIS BAD PRESS IS STARTING
TO TAINT MY SON'S FUTURE,
AND WE'VE GOT TO
PUT AN END TO IT.
- MICHAEL, IF THIS IS A LECTURE
ON HOW WE'RE ALL SUPPOSED
TO WHATEVER
AND BLAH, BLAH, BLAH,
WELL, YOU CAN SAVE IT,
'CAUSE WE ALL KNOW IT BY HEART.
- GOOD-BYE, MISSUS.
- WELL, THEN, LINDSAY,
YOU'LL BE HAPPY TO KNOW
THAT I HAVE A NEW IDEA.
I MET A PUBLICIST TODAY.
I'M GONNA HIRE HER.
WE NEED SOMEBODY
TO MAKE US LOOK GOOD.
- AND I SAY
IT'S A WASTE OF MONEY.
WE'RE PLENTY SYMPATHETIC
AS WE ARE.
IS THIS YOUR ONION?
- YES.
- WHAT'S IN THE FOIL?
- NOTHING.
IT'S A BALL OF FOIL FOR MY SON.
- HAVE A GREAT DAY, SWEETIE.
- I DON'T KNOW HOW SHE CAN'T.
- SO THIS PUBLICIST, MICHAEL,
IS SHE CUTE?
- I NEVER REALLY NOTICED.
narrator: IN FACT, MICHAEL
HAD NOTICED HER AT THE GYM,
BUT ONLY RECENTLY GOTTEN UP
THE NERVE TO TALK TO HER,
GIVING HIM A CHANCE TO WORK
ON HIS FLIRTING SKILLS--
- RACE YOU TO THE TOP
OF THE HILL.
narrator: WHICH HAD GOTTEN RUSTY
OVER THE YEARS.
- I'LL RACE YOU
TO THE TOP OF THE HILL.
- I BROUGHT A PICNIC LUNCH.
- HEY, THAT HILL WAS REALLY--
- JESSIE BOWERS.
IF YOU EVER HAVE
ANY PUBLIC RELATIONS NEEDS.
- MY RELATIONS ARE ALREADY
A LITTLE TOO PUBLIC.
I'M MICHAEL BLUTH.
- FROM THE BLUTH COMPANY?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- I'M GIVING YOU MY DIRECT LINE.
- OKAY, SURE. SHE'S--
SHE'S CUTE, I SUPPOSE.
I MEAN, NOW THAT YOU'RE MAKING
ME THINK ABOUT IT, SHE'S CUTE.
SHE'S A CUTIE.
SHE'S A LITTLE CUTIE PIE.
BUT I NEVER REALLY NOTICED.
- WHY DON'T YOU
JUST ASK HER OUT?
- THAT'S NOT AN OPTION.
- 'CAUSE YOU'RE SCARED?
- NO, BECAUSE OF GEORGE MICHAEL.
HE STILL HASN'T GOTTEN OVER
LOSING HIS MOTHER.
I JUST WANT TO GET HIM
THROUGH HIGH SCHOOL;
THEN WE'LL DEAL WITH ME, OKAY?
- SO YOU DIDN'T GET ANY WHILE
YOU WERE IN HIGH SCHOOL,
AND NOW YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET ANY
WHILE GEORGE MICHAEL'S
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
narrator: AND SO THE FAMILY
GATHERED AT THE MODEL HOME,
EAGER TO HEAR
THEIR NEW PUBLICIST'S PLAN.
- GET JOBS AND BEHAVE?
- INSTEAD OF US GETTING JOBS,
WHY DON'T YOU DO YOUR JOB AND
TELL EVERYONE WE'VE GOT JOBS?
- YOU KNOW, I HAVE A JOB.
- [coughs]
KISS ASS.
WELL, WE WERE ALL THINKING IT.
- I'M UNCLEAR ABOUT
WHAT IT IS EXACTLY YOU DO.
- EXCELLENT QUESTION.
WHAT A PUBLICIST DOES--
- NO, NO. I WAS TALKING
TO GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHEN DID YOU GET A JOB?
- AT THE BANANA STAND.
- OH! DUH.
I THOUGHT YOU MEANT LIKE
A PLUMBER OR SOMETHING.
AND I WAS LIKE,
"WHEN DID THAT HAPPEN?"
[laughs]
- JESSIE, WHY DON'T YOU JUST
GO AHEAD AND JUMP IN HERE.
IT'S A TOUGH GROUP
TO KEEP FOCUSED.
- WELL, I'M GOING
ON THE OFFENSIVE.
I WANT TO GET AN ARTICLE
IN THE PAPER TO SHOW
THAT THIS IS
A FUNCTIONAL FAMILY,
AND THIS IS A RELATABLE FAMILY.
- ARE WE ON? HELLO!
HELLO FROM PRISON!
THANKS TO JESSIE FOR SETTING UP
THIS TELELINK.
I'VE STARTED
A TORAH STUDY GROUP.
I'M VERY EXCITED ABOUT IT.
LOOKS LIKE--I DON'T KNOW--
LOOKS LIKE I HAVE
SOME POSSIBLE CONVERTS.
- YOUR FATHER'S RELIGIOUS NOW?
WE'LL PLAY THAT UP.
- IT'S VERY SYMPATHETIC.
- YEAH.
WHO DOESN'T LOVE THE JEWS?
- AND IT ALLOWS ME TO PUT
MICHAEL FRONT AND CENTER.
HE NEEDS TO BE
THE NEW FACE OF THIS FAMILY.
HE'S THE ONLY LIKABLE ONE
IN THE BUNCH--NO OFFENSE.
- NONE TAKEN.
- I'M SORRY.
ISN'T MICHAEL THE LEAST
LIKABLE ONE IN THE FAMILY?
- NO, THERE ARE VERY FEW
INTELLIGENT, ATTRACTIVE,
AND STRAIGHT MEN
IN THIS TOWN.
- WELL, THAT CERTAINLY
LEAVES ME OUT.
SHE--SHE SAID SINGLE.
YOU DID SAY "SINGLE," CORRECT?
I THOUGHT I--
- I DIDN'T QUITE HEAR THAT.
THE RECEPTION IS BAD.
BUT AS THE TALMUD TELLS US--
[TV static]
TO THE JACKAL
AS TO AN OXEN.
[laughs]
DID IT GET A LAUGH?
- I'M SORRY.
I'M STILL ON THE WHOLE
MICHAEL BEING LIKABLE THING.
YOU KNOW THAT HE'S ONLY HAD SEX
WITH, LIKE, FOUR WOMEN, RIGHT?
- LET'S FOCUS
ON YOUR LIKABILITY.
YOU'RE GOING TO START DOING SOME
CHARITY WORK WITH YOUR MAGIC.
- ACTUALLY, I'M KIND OF THE
CHARITABLE ONE OF THE FAMILY.
- I THINK IT'S BEST
IF YOU GOT A JOB.
- OH, COME ON!
I'M A PARENT.
I CARE ABOUT
MY DAUGHTER EVERY BIT AS MUCH
AS MICHAEL CARES ABOUT HIS SON.
- WHAT GRADE AM I IN?
- WHAT KIND OF JOB?
- SOMETHING WHERE
YOU'LL BE SEEN.
I REPRESENT CLOUDMIR VODKA,
AND THEY WANT SOMEONE TO PROMOTE
IT BY ORDERING IT AT A HOT BAR.
A PLACE LIKE RUD.
- OKAY. I'LL DO IT.
- AND TOBIAS,
YOU'RE A MEDICAL DOCTOR,
AND YOU'RE LIVING
AN ABSURD FANTASY AS AN ACTOR.
IT'S TIME TO GET REAL.
- WOW.
IT'S TOUGH TALK,
BUT I LIKE IT.
YOU'RE SAYING
LAND A MAJOR FILM.
- I'M SAYING GET
YOUR MEDICAL LICENSE BACK.
I'VE SET UP A HEARING
FOR TOMORROW IN BOSTON.
MICHAEL HAS GENEROUSLY DONATED
$1,100 FOR YOUR TRIP.
- I'M SORRY.
I TRULY BELIEVE THAT
THE UNIVERSE WANTS ME
TO BE AN ACTOR
AND NOT A DOCTOR.
I'M JUST WAITING
FOR A SIGN.
- HERE'S YOUR CASH.
UNIVERSAL SHUTTLE
PICKS YOU UP AT 8:00.
- ANY SIGN, REALLY.
- SORRY, SOME OF MY STUDENTS ARE
ARGUING THE SIGNIFICANCE
OF THE SHANK BONE
ON THE SEDER PLATE.
BUT THAT--NOT...
DO NOT WAG OUR GENITALS
AT ONE ANOTHER TO MAKE A POINT.
- THOUGHT-PROVOKING.
- AND LUCILLE,
PEOPLE THINK YOU'RE COLD.
- HANUKKAH CAN BE SPELLED
SO MANY WAYS. OH, GOD!
[all yelling]
beep!
- BUSTER.
- RIGHT HERE. READY TO GO.
AT YOUR SERVICE.
GET ME OUT THERE.
- I WANT YOU TO STAY IN.
PEOPLE FIND YOU
ODD AND ALIENATING.
YOU MAKE THEM UNEASY.
STAY OUT OF THE SPOTLIGHT.
- I SHALL BE NEITHER SEEN
NOR HEARD. WATCH ME.
- YOU CAN ALWAYS TELL
A MILFORD MAN.
narrator:
EACH WITH THEIR NEW CHARGE,
THE BLUTHS SET ABOUT
REDEFINING THEIR IMAGE.
TOBIAS WAS OFF TO LOS ANGELES
INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT,
DETERMINED TO RETURN
TO HIS FAMILY WITH A CAREER.
- WELL, THIS IS GREAT.
WHY WOULD ANYBODY TAKE A LIMO?
WHAT IS THIS, LIKE, $12?
WHY WOULD ANYBODY PAY MORE
THAN $12 TO GO TO THE AIRPORT?
NEXT STOP, LAX.
OH, COME ON!
WE'RE STOPPING AGAIN?
HOW MANY MORE STOPS
ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
HONESTLY, I HAVEN'T EVEN SEEN
THIS PART OF LOS ANG--
IS THAT SNOW?
REALLY, NOW.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I PAID 12 AMERICAN--
OH, MY GOD.
YOU ARE CARL WEATHERS,
THE ACTOR.
I WENT TO SAN FRANCISCO
TO ATTEND
YOUR STAGE FIGHTING WORKSHOP.
BUT YOU NEVER SHOWED UP.
- I GOT BUMPED FROM THAT FLIGHT.
HELL, THEY'LL GIVE YOU $300
IF YOU GET BUMPED.
IT'S THIS CRAZY LOOPHOLE
IN THE SYSTEM
THAT THE WRONG GUY DISCOVERED.
GUESS WHERE I WON'T BE GOING.
[laughs]
- YEAH. SO...
[chuckles]
I AM AN ACTOR TOO.
- OH. GOOD.
- WELL, I WANT TO BE.
I MEAN,
WITHOUT THE PROPER TRAINING,
I'M AFRAID I'M DOOMED
TO BE A DOCTOR.
- WELL, HELL,
I CAN TRAIN YOU.
- OH, WELL, I'M AFRAID
ALL I HAVE IS $1,100,
AND THAT'S FOR
THIS PLANE TICKET, SO...
- CHECK THIS OUT.
$1,100 IS EXACTLY WHAT I CHARGE
FOR ACTING CLASSES.
- NO, IT ISN'T!
- YEAH.
- WELL, WHAT ARE THE CHANCE--
[chuckles]
UNIVERSE,
YOU'VE DONE IT AGAIN.
narrator: MEANWHILE, GOB WAS
BEGINNING HIS CHARITY WORK
AT A LOCAL NURSING HOME.
- I'M GONNA NEED A VOLUNTEER
FOR MY NEXT ILLUSION,
THE AZTEC TOMB!
- A TOMB?
- OR BOX. BOX IS... FINE.
OH, YES! WELL, EXCELLENT.
LET'S GET YOU IN THE BOX.
[softly]
THERE'S A PANEL.
JUST FLIP IT AROUND,
CURL UP BEHIND IT,
DON'T MAKE ANY NOISE,
ALL RIGHT?
ANCIENT LORE HAS IT
THE AZTEC GODS PUT A CURSE
ON ANY MAN WHO DARE--
- WHAT?
- HE'S GONE.
narrator: BUSTER WAS ALSO
DOING HIS SHARE FOR THE FAMILY.
[phone ringing]
AND MICHAEL, AT JESSIE'S
INSISTENCE, WAS OUT ON THE TOWN.
- I HAVEN'T BEEN OUT TO DINNER
IN SO LONG,
I FEEL A LITTLE GUILTY.
- YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO BE GUILTY ABOUT.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
IN YOUR FAMILY
WHO'S EVER BEEN RESPONSIBLE.
- WELL, I'M CERTAINLY THE ONLY
ONE THAT'S EVER HELD A REAL JOB.
- OH, REALLY, MICHAEL?
WATCH THIS.
WOW! THIS CLOUDMIR'S
MAKING ME THINK FUZZY.
I HAVE ALMOST
NO JUDGMENT AT ALL.
- TWO MORE CLOUDMIRS, PLEASE.
- "ONLY ONE
WITH A REAL JOB."
- JESSIE, YOU'VE REALLY
BEEN DOING
A GREAT JOB WITH MY FAMILY.
- OH, GOOD. GET ONE
OF MICHAEL AND ME ON A DATE.
- SURE.
- THANK YOU.
- YOU'RE WELCOME, SIR.
- A DATE?
THIS IS A DATE NOW?
I THOUGHT THIS WAS
JUST BUSINESS.
- CAN'T IT BE
A LITTLE BIT OF BOTH?
- HOW WILL I KNOW
WHICH PART OF IT IS BUSINESS?
UH-OH.
CAN'T WAIT TO SEE WHICH PART
OF IT IS A DATE.
SHOW ME BUSINESS AGAIN.
[TV static]
- HEY, WHATCHA DOING?
- JUST TRYING TO GET
THE TV WORKING.
- OH, YEAH,
I TRIED THAT EARLIER.
I THINK IT'S STILL HOOKED UP
TO THE PRISON.
- SO WHEN THOSE GUYS
KEPT SAYING,
"HEY, YOU, BOY,"
THAT WAS ME?
I WAS THE BOY?
- SOUNDS LIKE IT.
SO HAVE YOU TOLD YOUR DAD YOU
DON'T WANT TO GO TO THAT SCHOOL?
- NO, I'M THINKING
OF JUST GOING.
I MEAN, THE GRADUATES GO ON
TO DO GREAT THINGS.
- I SUPPOSE, BUT THAT MEANS
WE WON'T BE GOING
TO THE SAME HIGH SCHOOL.
- MAN, IT JUST KEEPS
GETTING WORSE.
BUT HE'S MY DAD.
I DON'T WANT TO DISAPPOINT HIM.
- MAN, YOU AND I ARE
SO DIFFERENT.
IT'S LIKE WE'RE NOT
EVEN RELATED.
- THAT'D BE AMAZING.
OH, MY GOD.
- HEY, BUDDY.
- HEY, DAD.
- I'M SORRY THAT I'M SO LATE,
BUT I WAS WITH JESSIE.
THIS GIRL'S MAKING
SOME SERIOUS PROGRESS
IN GETTING YOU
INTO THAT SCHOOL.
SHE JUST BOOKED GOB A GIG
AT EARL MILFORD'S NURSING HOME.
YOU'RE GONNA BE A SHOO-IN.
- OH.
- [chuckles] SHE'S KINDA
SOMETHING, ISN'T SHE?
- YEAH, I GUESS.
- I MEAN, YOU KNOW, HEY, SHE IS
NO REPLACEMENT FOR YOUR MOM.
- OH, NO. NO WAY.
NOT AT ALL.
SHE'S JUST WORKING FOR US.
YOU'RE NOT DATING HER.
- NO, I AM NOT DATING HER.
ABSOLUTELY NOT DATING HER.
JUST YOU AND ME.
THE BLUTH BOYS.
- BLUTH BOYS.
- GOOD NIGHT, BUDDY.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- HEY.
- IS HE IN BED?
- HE'S ON HIS WAY.
HEY, LISTEN, LISTEN,
LISTEN, LISTEN.
THIS MIGHT BE MOVING A LITTLE
BIT TOO FAST FOR HIM.
I MEAN FOR--FOR US.
ME. UH, FOR ME.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE WE SHOULD
TAKE A STEP BACK
AND JUST KEEP THIS RELATIONSHIP
PROFESSIONAL.
- OH, I THINK THAT WOULD
TAKE ALL THE FUN OUT OF IT.
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
SERIOUSLY, SERIOUSLY.
YOU'RE AMAZING, BUT I JUST THINK
WE SHOULD SLOW DOWN.
- UH-HUH.
SO THE TWO MONTHS ON THE BIKE,
THAT WAS, WHAT, FOR MY HEALTH?
- WE HAD GREAT CONVERSATIONS.
SERIOUSLY,
THIS IS HARD FOR ME.
- THIS IS HARD FOR ME TOO.
I'VE GOT A LIFE TO GET ON TRACK,
AND I DON'T LIKE WASTING TIME,
SO LET'S DO THIS.
LET'S TAKE TWO STEPS BACK,
AND WHY DON'T YOU FIND YOURSELF
A NEW PUBLICIST.
- JESSIE.
NO, I WAS JUST SAYING YOUR NAME
AS YOU WALKED AWAY.
I DIDN'T--
I HAVE NO FOLLOW-UP.
[door opens and closes]
JESSIE.
narrator:
MICHAEL FELT BAD,
BUT HE FELT EVEN WORSE WHEN
HE GOT A CALL FROM HIS BROTHER.
- HELLO.
- IT'S GOB.
I'M LOOKING FOR JESSIE.
- WELL, SHE JUST LEFT, GOB.
WHAT'S WRONG?
- I NEED HER TO SPIN SOMETHING
FOR ME.
- WELL, THAT'S TOO BAD
BECAUSE I THINK SHE QUIT.
WHAT DO YOU NEED HER TO SPIN?
- MURDER.
narrator: MICHAEL WAS SUMMONED
TO HELP HIS BROTHER.
- MURDER, HUH? WHO DIED?
- MY CAREER.
- I'M GOING TO GO HOME NOW.
- I LOST A GUY.
I PUT HIM IN THE AZTEC TOMB,
AND HE DISAPPEARED.
- ISN'T THAT THE POINT?
- THIS WILL RUIN ME.
- HE'S PROBABLY FINE.
HE JUST ESCAPED.
- NO! I NEED JESSIE!
- WELL, SHE QUIT WHEN I TOLD HER
THAT I COULDN'T GO OUT WITH HER.
YOU KNOW, I HAVE TO DO
THE RIGHT THING FOR MY SON.
- THEN YOU BETTER GET HER BACK,
BECAUSE THE GUY I LOST
WAS EARL MILFORD.
- WHAT?
- I DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS HIM.
ALTHOUGH HE WAS
SPECTACULARLY QUIET IN THERE.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN ALWAYS TELL
A MILFORD MAN.
- GOB, HAVE YOU DESTROYED
MY CHANCE
AT GETTING
MY SON IN THAT SCHOOL?
- NOT WITH THE RIGHT SPIN.
JESSIE. GET HER BACK.
narrator: CHARGED WITH THE TASK
OF RENEWING HIS MEDICAL LICENSE,
TOBIAS WAS ENJOYING HIS FIRST
ACTING CLASS WITH CARL WEATHERS.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOUR POLICE
CAPTAIN TOLD YOU ABOUT ME,
BUT I'M A DIFFERENT
BREED OF COP.
I'M FROM THE STREETS,
AND I'M THE LAST COP
YOU'RE EVER GONNA WANNA
MESS WITH IN A DARKENED ALLEY.
DARK ALLEY. AND I--
[chuckles]
LISTEN, MR. WEATHERS,
I DON'T KNOW.
PERHAPS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW IF I'M CUT OUT
TO BE A--A DE NIRO
OR A REGIS OR A PINKETT-SMITH
OR WHAT HAVE YOU.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
TOBIAS.
DREAMS ARE WORTH
FIGHTING FOR.
NOW, ARE YOU GONNA BE A FIGHT,
OR ARE YOU GONNA BE A DOCTOR?
- YOU'RE RIGHT, CARL WEATHERS.
I SHOULD JUST MARCH
INTO THAT RESTAURANT
WHERE MY WIFE WORKS
AND TELL HER--
- YOUR WIFE WORKS
IN A RESTAURANT?
DO THEY GET A SHIFT MEAL,
OR DO THEY JUST PAY HALF-PRICE
ON SELECT MENU ITEMS?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- WELL, LET'S FIND OUT, MAN.
narrator: AND THE PRESS GOT HOLD
OF GOB'S STORY.
- WHERE IS EARL MILFORD?
- I--I DON'T KNOW, ALL RIGHT?
I PUT HIM IN A BOX.
I DIDN'T KILL HIM, ALL RIGHT?
AND DON'T EDIT THIS
FOR YOUR BROADCAST
SO IT LOOKS LIKE I'M SCREAMING,
"I KILLED EARL MILFORD."
- STARTLING CONFESSION,
TONIGHT AT 11:00.
narrator: MINUTES LATER,
GOB UNLOADED HIS EQUIPMENT
AND MADE A SURPRISING DISCOVERY.
- DON'T SEND ME BACK.
THEY ABUSE US.
IT'S NOT PLEASANT.
- EARL, I HAVE TO TAKE YOU BACK.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO CLEAR MY NAME.
- YOU'LL HAVE A NEW NAME: HERO.
- HERO.
THAT COULD WORK FOR ME.
narrator:
MEANWHILE, JESSIE DECIDED
TO PAY GEORGE MICHAEL A VISIT.
- HI, GEORGE MICHAEL.
PROUD OF YOURSELF?
- YEAH, ACTUALLY, I GOT A BUM
AWAY FROM THE STAND
WITHOUT HURTING HIS FEELINGS.
THAT WAS PRETTY SWEET.
- NO. I MEAN ABOUT YOUR FATHER.
ABOUT DENYING HIM
HIS CHANCE TO BE HAPPY.
- YOU'RE INTO THAT TOO?
I'M RUBBING OFF ON YOU, HUH?
- NO.
I WANT MY DAD TO BE HAPPY.
- WELL, IT'S TOO LATE NOW.
I'VE SEEN TO THAT.
DADDY LOST HIS SHOT AT HAPPY,
AND IT'S ALL YOUR FAULT, OPIE.
narrator:
JESSIE HAD GONE TOO FAR,
AND SHE HAD BEST WATCH
HER MOUTH.
- MICHAEL'S ABOUT TO BECOME
THE MOST UNLIKABLE MAN IN TOWN.
CHECK THE PAPERS.
- SHE KIND OF REMINDS ME
OF MY MOTHER.
narrator: AND LATER THAT NIGHT,
LINDSAY WAS WORKING AT RUD.
- YOU SEEM LIKE A MAN
OF TASTE AND CLASS.
- I'LL GIVE YOU $2,000
TO TOUCH ME.
- [chuckles]
OH, MY GOD. MY HUSBAND.
- YOU'RE MARRIED
TO CARL WEATHERS?
- [bleep] WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WHY AREN'T YOU IN BOSTON?
WHO'S HE?
- HIS NAME IS CARL WEATHERS,
AND HE'S MY NEW ACTING TEACHER.
AND, LINDSAY, HE'S TEACHING ME
ALL THESE VALUABLE LIFE LESSONS.
- I BUY ALL MY CARS
AT POLICE AUCTION.
- HE'S FULL OF STUFF LIKE THAT.
AND, LINDSAY, HE'S TEACHING ME
TO FOLLOW MY DREAMS.
- GIVE ME A BOURBON.
- ANY ROOM ON THAT TAB
FOR ME TO JUMP ON?
narrator: AND MICHAEL CAUGHT UP
WITH JESSIE.
- LISTEN, THANKS FOR COMING.
I WAS JUST--
I WAS DOING SOME THINKING.
AND, YOU KNOW, I PULLED AWAY,
AND THAT WAS WRONG.
I REALLY WANT
TO MAKE THIS WORK.
- GET AWAY FROM MY SON!
- HEY, MOM.
KIND OF ON A DATE HERE.
- YOU'LL CHANGE YOUR MIND
AFTER THIS.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL SAW THE STORY
THAT JESSIE HAD PLANTED.
- LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
SWEETIE.
WE MAY PICK ON EACH OTHER,
GET INTO LITTLE SCRAPES,
CALL EACH OTHER NAMES,
AND OCCASIONALLY STEAL
FROM EACH OTHER,
BUT THAT'S BECAUSE
WE'RE A FAMILY.
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT.
YOU DON'T GET TO DO THAT.
- "LINDSAY'S A COMBATIVE,
ENTITLED PRINCESS"?
I SHOULD HIRE SOMEBODY
TO KICK YOUR ASS FOR THAT.
- SAVE YOUR MONEY.
- YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'LL DO IT MYSELF.
- HEY, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
WE ARE NOT SETTLING THINGS
LIKE THAT ANYMORE, ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T NEED MY SON READING
ANY MORE ARTICLES
ABOUT US IN THE PAPER.
- OH, YOU AND YOUR SON.
STOP USING HIM AS AN EXCUSE
FOR EVERYTHING YOU DO.
- I SAW HIM TODAY.
HE'S FINE WITH US.
- WAIT, WHAT? YOU SAW HIM TODAY?
- YEAH.
I TOLD HIM HE WAS GETTING
IN THE WAY OF YOUR HAPPINESS.
- YOU DID?
YOU SAID THAT TO MY SON?
- YEAH.
- YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
LADIES?
- FOOD FIGHT!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OH, MY FACE!
I'M GONNA GET YOU GUYS!
STOP!
- THE PRESS IS HAVING
A LOVE AFFAIR
WITH HATING
THE BLUTH FAMILY,
AND THEY WERE THE CENTER OF
ANOTHER BRAWL THIS EVENING.
- I'M LOOKING AT $50,000 WORTH
OF MEDICAL BILLS HERE.
- WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE YOU WON'T
BE GETTING INTO THIS SCHOOL.
ARE YOU DISAPPOINTED?
- WELL, ARE YOU DISAPPOINTED?
- LOOK, GEORGE MICHAEL,
I WANT YOU TO TELL ME
HOW YOU FEEL, OKAY?
I DON'T WANT YOU TO WORRY SO
MUCH ABOUT HURTING MY FEELINGS.
- I DIDN'T WANT TO GO
TO THAT SCHOOL,
AND JESSIE'S A PSYCHO.
- THAT COULD'VE SAVED US
A LITTLE BIT OF TIME.
- BUT, DAD, IF YOU EVER WANT
TO DATE ANYONE ELSE,
THAT'S FINE WITH ME.
- YEAH?
THANKS, BUDDY.
- 'CAUSE YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
FOUR WOMEN, THAT IS KIND OF SAD.
- ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
- I MEAN, I KNOW YOU GOT MARRIED
IN COLLEGE,
BUT THAT WAS
YOUR SOPHOMORE YEAR.
YOU HAD
YOUR WHOLE FRESHMAN YEAR TO--
- OKAY, THAT'S ENOUGH HONESTY
FOR NOW.
THANK YOU.
GOOD NIGHT.
- THERE MUST HAVE BEEN GIRLS
AT PARTIES.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
GOB HOLDS A PRESS CONFERENCE
OF HIS OWN.
- AND NOW, PREPARE
TO CALL ME "HERO."
[cameras clicking]
HE'S RESTING, SO...
OH.
PICK A CARD.
OH, BOY.
narrator: AND BUSTER MOVES
TO THE KITCHEN.
[creaking]