male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
IT WAS MICHAEL'S SISTER'S
ANNIVERSARY,
AND HE'D CONVINCED HIS MOTHER
TO THROW A PARTY FOR HER.
- LINDSAY, HOW'S THIS
FOR AN ANNIVERSARY CAKE?
- ANNIVERSARY?
YOU ASKED ME TO THROW
A VALENTINE'S DAY PARTY.
- DID I?
- YOU TRICKED ME.
- I DECEIVED YOU, MOM.
TRICKED MAKES IT SOUND LIKE
WE HAVE A PLAYFUL RELATIONSHIP.
- TOUCHE
LUPE, UNTIE THE BALLOONS!
- MICHAEL, ALL ALONE
ON VALENTINE'S DAY?
HOW'S THAT POSSIBLE?
YOU SEEM LIKE SUCH
A ROMANTIC TO ME.
I-I-I CAN JUST SEE YOU SHOWING
UP ON SOME LUCKY GIRL'S PORCH
IN A TUXEDO
WITH A BOTTLE OF CHAMPAGNE.
- YEAH, WELL, IF I SHOW UP
WITH ALL THAT STUFF,
I COULD PROBABLY JUST GET AWAY
WITH SHORTS
AND A T-SHIRT, RIGHT?
WHICH IS GOOD, 'CAUSE I DON'T
EVEN HAVE A TUXEDO.
- SO YOU'RE SAYING THERE'S NO
ONE YOU'RE EVEN INTERESTED IN?
narrator: IN FACT, MICHAEL
HAD BECOME ENAMORED OF MARTA
WHEN GOB WAS HAVING SECOND
THOUGHTS ABOUT THE RELATIONSHIP.
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
narrator: BUT WHEN
GOB RECOMMITTED TO HER...
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
narrator: MICHAEL DECIDED TO DO
THE NOBLE THING AND LET HER GO.
- MM, THERE WAS SOMEBODY
FOR A LITTLE WHILE,
BUT IT WAS TOO MUCH
OF A BROTHER--BOTHER.
- THAT CAN'T FEEL GOOD.
- IT'S FINE; I'M OVER IT.
I'M OKAY BY MYSELF, YOU KNOW?
I REALLY JUST WANT TO FOCUS
ON MY FAMILY'S HAPPINESS.
THAT'S WHY I THREW THIS PARTY.
I MEAN, 14 YEARS, HUH?
YOU'VE GOT TO BE DOING
SOMETHING RIGHT.
- WELL, IF YOU CALL NOT FILING
FOR DIVORCE "SOMETHING RIGHT."
BUT I GUESS
WE KEEP IT INTERESTING.
- WHERE'S TOBIAS?
- HE'S ON THE BALCONY HAVING
MARGARITAS WITH CARL WEATHERS.
narrator: TOBIAS HAD RECENTLY
HIRED ACTOR CARL WEATHERS
AS A DRAMA COACH.
- DO YOU SEE ME MORE AS
THE RESPECTED DRAMATIC ACTOR,
OR MORE
OF THE BELOVED COMIC ACTOR?
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
THERE'S STILL PLENTY OF MEAT
ON THAT BONE.
NOW, YOU TAKE THIS HOME,
THROW IT IN A POT,
ADD SOME BROTH, A POTATO--
BABY, YOU GOT A STEW GOING.
- YES, THAT'S FINE.
BUT I WOULD LIKE TO FOCUS
ON MY ACTING, MR. WEATHERS.
I DID GIVE YOU
MY LAST $1,100.
- LET ME TELL YOU A LITTLE STORY
ABOUT ACTING.
I WAS DOING THIS SHOWTIME MOVIE,
"HOT ICE," WITH ANNE ARCHER.
NEVER ONCE
TOUCHED MY PER DIEM.
I GO TO CRAFT SERVICE,
GET SOME RAW VEGGIES,
BACON, CUP OF SOUP--
[chuckles]
BABY, I HAD A STEW GOING.
- I THINK I'D LIKE
MY MONEY BACK.
narrator: LIKE HIS FATHER,
GEORGE MICHAEL HAD BEEN
NURSING AN IMPOSSIBLE CRUSH.
IT WAS ON HIS COUSIN, MAEBY.
AND WITH NO ONE TO TALK TO,
HE WAS LOOKING
FOR SOME KIND OF DIRECTION.
- JUST GIVE ME A SIGN.
[chuckles] FIRST ONE'S OBVIOUS.
OKAY.
narrator: HE CONTINUED
TO LOOK FOR A SIGN.
UNTIL FINALLY...
- "MAYBE TONIGHT."
- WHAT ARE THE CHANCES?
narrator:
ACTUALLY, "MAYBE TONIGHT"
WAS A VERY POPULAR
CANDY SLOGAN,
AND THE CHANCES
WERE ONE IN EIGHT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- JUST TRYING TO THROW STUFF
AT MY DAD'S HEAD,
BUT THE WIND
KEEPS TAKING IT.
- OH, COOL.
SO, I, UH--
I FOUND THIS.
I THOUGHT IT WAS LIKE
A ONE-IN-A-MILLION THING.
IT JUST MADE ME THINK OF YOU.
- OH, PERFECT.
- TRYING TO MAKE MY RELATION--
I SAW THAT.
narrator: AND LUCILLE
FOUND A WAY
TO FORCE A WEDGE
INTO HER SON'S RELATIONSHIP.
- LUCILLE, GUESS WHO'S COMING
TO DINNER?
I'VE INVITED CARL
TO DINE WITH US NEXT TUESDAY.
- MOTHER, YOU KNOW
I HAVE CLASS ON TUESDAY.
- [sighs] OH, HOW SILLY OF ME.
WELL, THEN PERHAPS THE TWO
OF YOU CAN HAVE DINNER ALONE.
- OH, WELL,
I NEVER SAY NO TO DINNER,
WITH A BEAUTIFUL LADY THAT IS.
- DO YOU LIKE HAM?
- NO. I LOVE IT.
[both laughing]
narrator: AND THE FAMILY
GATHERED TO WATCH A VIDEOTAPE
GEORGE SR. HAD SENT LINDSAY AND
TOBIAS FOR THEIR ANNIVERSARY.
- HELLO, I'M GEORGE BLUTH,
AND FOR THE NEXT 45 MINUTES,
LET ME TAKE YOU ON A JOURNEY--
- GOOD GRIEF!
HE SENT US ONE OF HIS
IDIOT VIDEOTAPES.
- FIRST THIS.
- YOU'VE SEEN
GEORGE BLUTH ON VIDEOTAPE.
- YOU HAVE GOT TO LEARN
TO BE ALONE.
I CHEATED, AND I LIED,
AND I WHORED AROUND.
- "CAGED WISDOM"
CHANGED MY LIFE.
- NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO OWN
THE ENTIRE GEORGE BLUTH
"CAGED WISDOM" LIBRARY
FOR ONLY FOUR PAYMENTS
OF $19.95.
- THIS WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
MY ANNIVERSARY TOAST.
- YEAH, AND THIS WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE MY VALENTINE'S DAY PARTY.
SPEAKING OF WHICH...
LUPE, WHERE ARE
THOSE BALLOONS?
- YOU WANT BALLOONS?
- SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH--
all: SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH,
SPEECH, SPEECH,
SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH--
- COME ON, SPEECH.
all: SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH,
SPEECH--
narrator:
THE FAMILY CONTINUED TO CHANT,
"SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH,"
FOR NO ONE IN PARTICULAR.
- ALL RIGHT.
all: SPEECH, SPEECH.
- GEE, AFTER ALL THAT,
I WAS KIND OF HOPING
SOMEBODY WOULD MAKE A SPEECH.
- SPEECH, SPEECH, SPEECH--
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SAY SOMETHING.
- TYPICAL.
- WE'VE ALL HAD
A TOUGH COUPLE OF MONTHS.
I THINK WE'RE ALL REALLY
FIGURING OUT WHO WE ARE
AND WHAT WE REALLY
NEED IN LIFE.
AND THAT CAN BE PAINFUL.
HOWEVER, YOU CAN'T REALLY
HEAL YOURSELF
UNTIL YOU STOP
LIVING A LIE, YOU KNOW.
BUT, UH, I-I PROMISE
THAT WE'RE ALL GONNA BE
A LOT HAPPIER IN THE LONG RUN.
SO, ON A VERY UNUSUAL
VALENTINE'S DAY,
CHEERS TO MOM AND DAD,
TO BUSTER AND LUCILLE--
- [chuckling]
DON'T FORGET MY GIRLFRIEND.
- THAT'S WHO I MEANT.
TO LINDSAY AND TOBIAS,
TO GEORGE MICHAEL AND--
I ALMOST SAID GEORGE MICHAEL
AND MAEBY [chuckles].
- OH. [laughing]
- UM, TO GOB AND MARTA.
- MMM.
- TO LOVE AND HAPPINESS.
I LOVE YOU ALL, MARTA.
narrator: AND MARTA REALIZED
IT WAS MICHAEL, NOT GOB,
WHO HAD EVERYTHING SHE HAD BEEN
LOOKING FOR IN A MAN.
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
- I WAS THINKING ABOUT
THAT TOAST YOU GAVE
AT MY ANNIVERSARY PARTY.
SO, I WANT TO GET A DIVORCE.
- WHAT?
- DO YOU THINK I SHOULD USE
OUR ATTORNEY, BARRY,
OR JUST
KIND OF BOLT IN THE NIGHT?
I'M LEANING TOWARD
BOLT IN THE NIGHT, BUT--
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
LINDSAY, I WASN'T TALKING
ABOUT GETTING A DIVORCE.
- OH, MICHAEL.
[sighs] IT'S TIME.
THE MAN'S
PSYCHOLOGICALLY INCAPABLE
OF TAKING
ALL OF HIS CLOTHES OFF.
narrator: IN FACT,
TOBIAS WAS A NEVER-NUDE.
AS OF YET, THE D.S.M.-IV
HAS NOT ACKNOWLEDGED
THE AFFLICTION.
- I DON'T KNOW, LINDSAY.
I MEAN, WHO AM I TO JUDGE?
ON THE OTHER HAND,
I AM DOING IT ANYWAY,
SO LET ME SUGGEST,
BEFORE YOU TALK DIVORCE,
AT LEAST CONSIDER A SEPARATION.
YOU KNOW, YOU DO HAVE A KID.
- I KNOW.
I WAS GONNA TAKE HER
WITH ME IN THE NIGHT.
SHE'S PART OF THE BOLT.
- LINDSAY.
- ALL RIGHT.
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
[phone rings]
- HELLO?
- HEY, BROTHER.
I JUST WANT TO TELL YOU
HOW MUCH I ENJOYED
YOUR SPEECH YESTERDAY.
YOU KNOW, ABOUT FAMILY AND--
AND BEING TRUE TO OURSELVES.
- OH, WELL, I'M--
I'M GLAD IT MADE AN IMPACT.
- YEAH.
I NEVER WANT TO LOOK
AT MOM AGAIN.
- [sighs] WHAT HAPPENED?
- WELL, I CAN'T REALLY TALK.
SHE MIGHT BE LISTENING IN.
DO YOU KNOW SHE TRIED TO
SET UP MY GIRLFRIEND WITH A MAN?
THIS HAS TO STOP.
- YOU KNOW, THAT'S NOT REALLY
WHAT I WAS GOING FOR.
- I'M A MAN, MIKE!
I'M A MAN.
- CAN I THROW OUT THIS YOGURT?
- BUSTER, TWO THINGS.
FIRST OF ALL,
I THINK IT MIGHT BE TIME
FOR YOU TO MOVE OUT, YOU KNOW?
AND SECONDLY,
YOU DON'T WANT TO TAKE ANY
CHANCES WITH YOGURT, MOM.
JUST LET HER THROW IT OUT.
- HE-HELLO?
WHO'S ON THIS PHONE?
- HUH?
- MICHAEL?
- HEY.
- GREAT SPEECH LAST NIGHT.
- OH, REALLY?
WHAT DID IT INSPIRE
YOU TO DO, KILL SOMEBODY?
- GETTING THERE.
MARTA'S CHEATING ON ME.
- WHAT?
- YEAH, CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
- THAT'S CRAZY, GOB.
SHE'S NOT A CHEATER.
I MEAN, IF SHE WERE TO CHEAT,
I'D LIKE TO THINK SHE'D CHEAT--
YOU'RE THE CHEATER.
- THAT'S HOW I KNOW
ALL THE SIGNS.
LAST NIGHT SHE WAS
ALL DISTANT AND WEIRD.
WOULDN'T LET ME MAKE LOVE
TO HER ON MOM'S BED.
I DON'T EVEN WANT
TO TELL YOU
WHAT SHE WOULDN'T
LET ME DO TO HER IN THE CAR.
AND THEN TODAY, I OVERHEAR
HER TALKING ON THE PHONE
ABOUT SOMEBODY
ALL SUPER SILENTLY.
ALL IN SPANISH.
narrator: IN FACT,
MARTA WAS ON THE PHONE
WITH HER MOTHER
TALKING ABOUT MICHAEL.
- SHE KEPT USING THIS GUY'S
NAME, LIKE, "HERMANO."
- LET ME
TELL YOU SOMETHING, GOB.
WE'RE GONNA TRACK
THIS "HERMANO" DOWN, OKAY,
AND WE'RE GONNA NAIL HIM.
'CAUSE IF ANYONE'S
GONNA GO OUT WITH THAT GIRL,
IT'S GONNA BE ONE OF US.
- RIGHT--ME.
- AND I'M OKAY WITH THAT.
- I DON'T GET IT.
WHY DO WE HAVE TO CHANGE ROOMS?
- COUSINS OF THE OPPOSITE GENDER
SHOULDN'T BE SHARING A ROOM.
- BUT THAT'S JUST THE POINT.
I MEAN, WE'RE COUSINS.
YOU KNOW, GENDER HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
I MEAN, COUSINS CAN
BUNK TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHY THEY CALL IT
"BUNKIN' COUSINS."
- ACTUALLY, THEY CALL IT
"KISSIN' COUSINS."
- WE'RE NOT KISSING!
THAT'S THE POINT!
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS CONCERNED
THAT TOBIAS HAD SEEN
THE CANDY HEART
THAT SAID "MAYBE TONIGHT"
AND HAD FIGURED OUT
THAT HE HAD
A CRUSH ON HIS COUSIN.
- BESIDES, I DON'T EVEN CARE.
YOU KNOW, FIRST YOU SAID
SHARE A ROOM WITH HER,
I SHARED A ROOM WITH HER.
NOW YOU'RE SAYING DON'T SHARE
A ROOM WITH HER.
FINE.
I'M JUST DOING WHATEVER YOU SAY.
YOU KNOW, THE ADULTS MAKING
ALL THE DECISIONS AROUND HERE.
WHY AM I IN TROUBLE?
- YOU'RE NOT IN TROUBLE.
WE'RE ALL JUST GONNA HAVE
A MORE NORMAL ARRANGEMENT.
I'M GONNA SLEEP
WITH MY DAUGHTER,
AND YOU'RE
GONNA SLEEP WITH MY HUSBAND.
narrator: BUSTER HAD TAKEN
MICHAEL'S ADVICE
AND DECIDED
TO CONFRONT HIS MOTHER.
- [sniffing]
"BECAUSE YOU KNOW I DON'T
APPRECIATE HOW YOU TREAT ME.
I AM NOT A CHILD, MOTHER."
[sniffs]
- [sighs] BLOW.
- NO, MOTHER!
I CAN BLOW MYSELF.
AND YOU HAVE INTERFERED
FOR THE LAST TIME.
- FINE.
GO.
MOVE OUT.
narrator: SO, BUSTER
LOADED UP HIS POSSESSIONS
AND EMANCIPATED HIMSELF
FROM HIS MOTHER.
- [muffled laughter]
OH, HEY, BUSTER.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD CLASS.
- I THOUGHT YOU HAD CLASS.
MY BROTHER-IN-LAW FIRES YOU,
AND YOU MOVE IN
ON MY GIRLFRIEND?
- COME ON, NOW.
WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS IS JUST PURELY
A SOCIAL CALL.
YOU KNOW, JUST TWO ADULTS
GETTING A STEW ON, MAN.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS,
BUT IT SOUNDS DISGUSTING.
- HEY, BUSTER.
GEE, I THOUGHT YOU HAD CLASS.
- I THOUGHT YOU HAD CLASS!
I WANT TO MOVE IN WITH YOU.
I'M TIRED OF MY MOM
TRYING TO CONTROL ME.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE DOING THIS
BECAUSE YOU WANT TO BE WITH ME,
AND NOT BECAUSE YOU WANT
TO GET EVEN WITH YOUR MOTHER?
- THIS ISN'T ABOUT MY MOTHER.
BESIDES, IT'S THE ONLY WAY
I'M EVER GONNA GET HER
TO RESPECT ME.
- BUSTER, THIS IS EXACTLY WHY
OUR RELATIONSHIP DOES NOT WORK.
- OUR RELATIONSHIP DOESN'T WORK?
- NO, NOT AS LONG
AS YOU KEEP GETTING ME
ALL MIXED UP WITH YOUR MOTHER.
- IT IS EXACTLY THE OPPOSITE.
I'M LEAVING
MY MOTHER FOR YOU.
YOU'RE REPLACING
MY MOTHER.
- YOU NEED SOME TIME.
- HUH?
[door closes]
narrator: MEANWHILE, MICHAEL WAS
FOLLOWING MARTA TO CONFIRM
GOB'S SUSPICIONS
ABOUT HER AFFAIR.
FIRST, HE SAW HER BUY A PRESENT
AT AN EXCLUSIVE MEN'S STORE.
THE TRAIL THEN LED MICHAEL
TO THE SET OF MARTA'S
SPANISH-LANGUAGE SOAP OPERA.
- EXCUSE ME.
I'M LOOKING FOR "HERMANO."
- OH, MI HERMANO.
- THERE, IN THE GREEN?
- MM-HMM.
- GREAT, THANKS, GRACIAS.
- [speaking Spanish]
- "HERMANO."
ARE YOU "HERMANO"?
- AH, MI HERMANO?
- THAT'S THE GUY WHO JUST--
- MM-HMM.
- SON OF A BITCH.
- [speaking Spanish]
- MARTA.
- I HAD TO SEE YOU.
HE MOVED OUT.
- MOVED OUT?
BUSTER DID?
- I KNOW IT'S FOR HIS OWN GOOD,
BUT I'M WORRIED.
- WELL, HE'S GONNA BE FINE.
- I'M NOT WORRIED ABOUT HIM.
I'VE NEVER LIVED
IN THE APARTMENT ALONE.
I'M NOT SURE I'M UP TO THIS.
- ALL RIGHT.
SHH, SHH, SHH.
LISTEN, I KNOW YOU THINK
I'M GOING AFTER THE $49,
BUT I WANT--
I WANT YOU TO WATCH
A LITTLE "CAGED WISDOM."
- NOT THIS GARBAGE AGAIN.
- THERE IS JOY
IN SOLITUDE, LUCILLE.
TRY BEING ALONE.
I-I-IT JUST MIGHT
MAKE YOU HAPPIER.
HONEY, MY HAPPIEST TIMES HERE
ARE ALONE.
- [sighs]
- HEY, BRUNO, ANY CHANCE
THAT THE HOLE IS AVAILABLE
BETWEEN 4:00 AND 6:00?
- I DON'T EVEN WANT TO KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS.
narrator: WITH NOWHERE ELSE
TO GO,
BUSTER ARRIVED
AT THE MODEL HOME.
- BUSTER BLUTH.
- HEY, BROTHER-IN-LAW.
- GOOD NEWS.
CARL GOT ME AN AUDITION.
- CARL WEATHERS?
- I THINK THE WORLD
IS ABOUT TO FALL IN LOVE
WITH "FRIGHTENED INMATE \#2."
- WELL, AT LEAST HE GAVE
YOU SOMETHING.
CARL WEATHERS
TOOK EVERYTHING FROM ME.
MY ENTIRE LIFE
JUST CAME CRASHING DOWN,
AND IT'S ALL HIS FAULT.
I WILL NEVER LOVE AGAIN.
- HELLO.
- OH, MY GOD.
- IS EVERYTHING OKAY?
narrator: AND SUDDENLY,
BUSTER REALIZED MARTA
WAS THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
HE HAD EVER SEEN.
- I'VE BEEN DATING AN OLD LADY.
- IS MICHAEL HERE?
- I-I DON'T--
I DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS.
narrator: IN FACT,
MICHAEL WAS JUST RETURNING
FROM HIS DAY OF FOLLOWING MARTA.
- WELL, I LOST HER.
- MICHAEL.
- MARTA.
- I'M SO GLAD I CAUGHT YOU.
- YOU CAUGHT ME?
- YES.
- OH.
- FIRST OF ALL, THANK YOU
SO MUCH FOR THE LOVELY PARTY
AND FOR MAKING ME FEEL
SO WELCOME IN YOUR FAMILY.
- YEAH, SURE.
- WE LOVE YOU!
CAN I--CAN I STAY HERE
FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
- WELL, EVERYBODY'S ALREADY
SHARING A BEDROOM
BUT ME, BUSTER.
- OH, PERFECT.
- SO, I WAS HOPING YOU MIGHT
HAVE SOME TIME TO TALK.
THERE'S SOMETHING I NEED--
[cell phone ringing]
MAYBE WE COULD HAVE DINNER?
- HELLO?
- SHE'S AT THE HOUSE.
SHE'S AT THE HOUSE!
- ONE SECOND.
- I'M GONNA SPEAK VERY CAREFULLY
IN CASE SHE'S WITH YOU.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
- RIGHT ABOUT WHAT--SHE'S THERE?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHO'S WITH YOU?
IF IT'S MARTA, SAY "NOBODY."
- NOBODY.
- WELL, NOW I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON.
[sighs]
SO, DID YOU FIND OUT ANYTHING?
I-I'M DYING HERE, MICHAEL.
D-DID YOU FIND THAT GUY?
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
- [whispering] "HERMANO."
- "HERMANO."
- IS THAT YOUR BROTHER?
- HMM?
NO, HE'S UPSTAIRS, REMEMBER?
LISTEN, I GOT TO GO.
SOMEBODY WANTS TO
TAKE ME OUT TO DINNER.
- SOMEBODY?
- NOBODY.
- WHY DON'T I JUST COME IN?
I'M RIGHT OUTSIDE.
- NO, NO.
NOT--NOT A GOOD IDEA.
SOMEBODY WANTS TO TALK TO ME
ABOUT SOMETHING.
- AH, SHE WANTS
TO TALK TO YOU--GOT IT.
FOR SOME REASON
WOMEN FEEL SAFE AROUND YOU.
MAYBE BECAUSE YOU'VE ONLY
HAD SEX FOUR TIMES.
- NO, FOUR WOMEN!
NOT FOUR TIMES!
AND THEY TALK TO ME
BECAUSE I TALK TO THEM.
- LOOK, GO TO DINNER.
LET'S GET TO THE BOTTOM OF THIS
"HERMANO" STUFF, BROTHER.
- YEP, GREAT.
- GREAT.
- HEY, ABOUT DINNER.
I'D LOVE TO.
narrator:
TOBIAS ARRIVED AT HIS AUDITION
FOR "FRIGHTENED INMATE \#2."
[chattering]
THE COMPETITION
FRIGHTENED TOBIAS,
WHICH HE FELT HE COULD
USE IN HIS PERFORMANCE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THIS MADE HIM MORE CONFIDENT,
WHICH FRIGHTENED HIM AGAIN.
- I'M READY.
narrator: THAT NIGHT, MAEBY
MOVED IN TO LINDSAY'S ROOM.
- ISN'T THIS FUN?
IT'S LIKE A SLUMBER PARTY.
OOH.
- THAT'S IT!
TELL ME WHAT'S UP
WITH YOU AND DAD.
- NOTHING.
NOTHING'S WRONG
WITH YOUR FATHER AND ME.
WE HAVE A--A WONDERFUL,
CLOSE RELATIONSHIP.
AND CAN I LET YOU IN
ON A LITTLE SECRET, HMM?
HAVING HIM IN THE NEXT ROOM
MAKES ME MISS HIM ALL THE MORE.
- MOM, PLEASE.
HE'S GOT A BIG-BOY CRUSH
ON ACTION JACKSON.
- I KNOW.
HOW CAN I COMPETE WITH THAT?
OKAY, WE'RE HAVING
A LITTLE FIGHT RIGHT NOW.
BUT DON'T WORRY, DARLING.
OKAY?
MOMMY AND DADDY
AREN'T GOING ANYWHERE.
- OKAY.
I'M GONNA GO
UNPACK MY SUITCASE.
- NO!
WE MAY HAVE TO BOLT.
narrator: TOBIAS MOVED IN
TO GEORGE MICHAEL'S ROOM.
- YOU KNOW, MAEBY AND I
WERE COOL WITH EACH OTHER.
AND I MEAN, YOU MUST REALLY
MISS YOUR WIFE.
IT'S PRACTICALLY STILL
YOUR ANNIVERSARY.
- 14 YEARS OF LIES.
YES, I'M THE DOCTOR.
THE PERFECT HUSBAND.
THE BIG MANLY MAN.
THE BIG STRONG DADDY.
DO YOU KNOW THE LAST TIME
THAT I MADE LOVE TO MY WIFE?
- NO.
- I'LL TELL YOU WHEN.
- NO, DON'T.
- SEE, NOTHING HAS EVER
BEEN EASY FOR US.
I MEAN, THE ONLY REASON
SHE WENT OUT WITH ME
WAS TO PISS OFF HER BOYFRIEND.
THE ONLY REASON
SHE EVER MARRIED ME
WAS TO PISS OFF HER MOTHER.
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
WE COULDN'T CONCEIVE.
SO THERE WAS THAT FAMOUS ORDEAL.
- WH-WHAT DO YOU MEAN YOU
COULDN'T CONCEIVE?
WAS MAEBY ADOPTED?
[cell phone ringing]
WHAT, IS SHE NOT
REALLY RELATED TO ME?
IS SHE JUST SOME GIRL I KNOW?
- [whispering]
AH, IT'S CARL WEATHERS.
YES, CARL WEATHERS.
I DID?
THAT'S--THAT'S WONDERFUL.
- THAT'S--
[phone beeps]
HUH! I BOOKED IT!
I BOOKED THE ACTING JOB!
DID YOU HEAR THAT, LINDSAY?
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN SLEEPING
WITH "FRIGHTENED INMATE \#2."
narrator:
AND LUCILLE WAS EXPERIENCING
BEING ALONE FOR THE FIRST TIME.
UNABLE TO SLEEP,
SHE DECIDED TO WATCH TV.
- YOU HAVE GOT
TO LEARN TO BE ALONE.
narrator: THEN SHE REMEMBERED
THAT WITH NO ONE TO DISTURB,
SHE COULD TURN UP THE VOLUME
AS LOUD AS SHE WANTED.
- "CAGED WISDOM" TEACHES YOU
THAT YOU HAVE
TO FIND THE JOY WITHIN YOURSELF.
- [singing from radio]
SHH, HERE COMES MAMA
MAMA'S TALKIN' LOUD
narrator:
AND THAT'S WHEN LUCILLE REALIZED
THAT SHE JUST MIGHT LIKE
BEING ALONE AFTER ALL.
- [singing] MAMA'S LETTIN' LOOSE
narrator: THE NEXT NIGHT,
MICHAEL HAD DINNER
WITH MARTA AT HER HOUSE,
HOPING TO FINALLY GET
THE ANSWERS HE WAS LOOKING FOR.
- SO, UM, ABOUT GOB.
HOW'S THAT GOIN'?
- WELL, AS YOU SAID,
FINDING OUT WHO YOU REALLY ARE,
IT CAN BE PAINFUL.
BUT YOU CAN'T LIVE A LIE.
- NO, I CAN'T.
BUT SOME PEOPLE FIND A WAY
TO MAKE THAT WORK.
- YES, BUT SOMETIMES
WORKING AT SOMETHING,
IT'S A WAY TO NOT DEAL
WITH SOME OTHER THING.
- BUT HE WHO OFTEN SUGGESTS,
UH, WORKING ON ANOTHER THING,
WHICH, WHEN
THE FIRST THING IS NOT--
- WILL YOU EXCUSE ME
FOR A MOMENT?
- YES.
SURE.
- WHAT THE HELL
IS HE TALKING ABOUT?
- THE HELL IS SHE TALKING ABOUT?
- CAN I HAVE A PIECE OF CAKE?
narrator: AND MICHAEL
SAW AN OPPORTUNITY
TO GET THE INFORMATION
HE WASN'T GETTING FROM MARTA
FROM HER SON.
- I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I GOT--I GOT A DEAL
FOR YOU, PARTNER.
I'LL GIVE YOU WHAT YOU WANT
IF YOU GIVE ME WHAT I WANT.
TELL ME EVERYTHING
YOU KNOW ABOUT "HERMANO."
- HERMANO?
- DOES YOUR MOTHER
LOVE "HERMANO?"
- SI, MI HERMANO.
- HE'S HERE?
- SHH, HE'S SLEEPING.
- DON'T GO IN THERE.
- WHY, IS THERE SOMETHING
YOU DON'T WANT ME TO SEE?
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- YOU KNOW, WE CAN
KEEP GOING AROUND IN CIRCLES,
BUT MAYBE ONE OF US
SHOULD JUST COME OUT AND SAY
WHAT IT IS WE WANT TO SAY.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S NOT WORKING WITH GOB.
- WHY DOESN'T HE KNOW THAT?
YOU KNOW YOU COULD HAVE
JUST COME OUT AND TOLD HIM,
YOU KNOW, INSTEAD OF LYING
AND SNEAKING AROUND,
MOVING ON TO THE NEXT GUY.
I DIDN'T THINK YOU WERE
THAT KIND OF A PERSON.
YOU KNOW, I THOUGHT YOU AND I
SHARED THE SAME VALUES.
I THOUGHT YOU AND I
COULD'VE BEEN, UH--
NO, FORGET IT.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW I HAD YOU SO WRONG.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
I SHOULD HAVE TOLD HIM
BEFORE I INVITED YOU HERE.
THIS CAN NEVER BE.
narrator: THEN HE NOTICED
THE GIFT HE HAD SEEN HER BUY.
- [sighs]
WHAT DOES "TE AMO" MEAN?
- I LOVE YOU.
- HMM.
AND WHO'S IN THERE?
- MI HERMANO.
- BROTHER.
I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
GEORGE MICHAEL
BEGINS AN INVESTIGATION.
- SO, YOU WANT TO GO
TO THE MOVIES?
OW!
- I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN I GET BACK FROM THE LAB.
narrator: TOBIAS FACES
HIS GREATEST ACTING CHALLENGE.
- THERE'S A SHOWER SCENE?
I HAVE TO BE NUDE?
- WELL, YOU DON'T SHOWER
WITH YOUR CLOTHES ON,
NOW, DO YOU?
narrator: AND BUSTER REBOUNDS
FROM LUCILLE 2.
- YO TE QUIERO MUCHO.
TE AMO, MARTA.
TE AMO.