male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
narrator:
MICHAEL BLUTH WAS INFATUATED
WITH HIS BROTHER'S
GIRLFRIEND, MARTA,
A SPANISH-LANGUAGE
SOAP OPERA STAR.
BUT WHEN HE FOUND OUT
SHE WAS INTERESTED
IN A MAN NAMED HERMANO,
HE CONFRONTED HER.
UNFORTUNATELY,
HE DISCOVERED TOO LATE
THAT "HERMANO"
IN SPANISH MEANT "BROTHER,"
AND THE PERSON MARTA
WAS INFATUATED WITH
WAS, IN FACT, HIMSELF.
THIS WAS DISTRACTING MICHAEL
THE NEXT DAY WHEN HE WENT
TO MEET HIS FATHER'S
ATTORNEY AT PRISON.
- LOOK, THERE IS NOTHING TO IT.
IT'S AN ARRAIGNMENT.
THEY ANNOUNCE THE CHARGES.
HOWEVER, IT WOULD HELP
IF YOU ALL SHOWED UP,
LOOKING LIKE A LOVING,
SUPPORTIVE FAMILY.
- FOR HOW LONG?
- TEN MINUTES, TOPS.
- SEE IF YOU CAN
GET IT DOWN TO FIVE.
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE I SHOULD
CONFESS THESE CRIMES,
SAVE EVERYBODY THE TROUBLE.
- OH, GET OFF THE MOUNT.
YOU'RE COMING HOME, GUILTY
OR SOMEHOW FOUND NOT GUILTY.
[phone ringing]
- HELLO?
- WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?
I'M WAITING TO HEAR ABOUT
MARTA AND THIS HERMANO GUY.
- YEAH, I CHECKED IT OUT.
I DO NOT THINK
THAT SHE'S CHEATING.
- I'M GOING OVER TO MARTA'S.
- NO, NO, NO.
DON'T--DON'T DO THAT, OKAY?
JUST LAY LOW, BE COOL,
AND I'LL TALK TO HER AGAIN.
THAT WAY YOU DON'T LOOK
SO DESPERATE, YOU KNOW?
- YOU'RE A GOOD GUY, MON FRERE.
THAT MEANS "BROTHER" IN FRENCH.
I DON'T KNOW WHY I KNOW THAT.
I TOOK FOUR YEARS OF SPANISH.
narrator: SO MICHAEL
WENT TO SPEAK WITH MARTA
ABOUT THE MISUNDERSTANDING
FROM THE NIGHT BEFORE.
- I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY.
- NO, I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY.
I'M SO ASHAMED THAT
I WAS SO DISRESPECTFUL
TO YOUR BROTHER.
- OH, WHO CARES?
NOBODY RESPECTS HIM.
YOU SEE, MARTA,
I HAVE BEEN INTERESTED IN YOU
SINCE THE FIRST DAY THAT WE MET.
- REALLY?
- YEAH, YEAH.
- IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WE LIVE BY A CODE,
YOU AND I--TO HONOR FAMILY.
- YES, THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT ATTRACTED ME TO YOU--
YOUR SENSE OF RIGHT AND WRONG.
I ALSO LIKE YOUR HAIR
AND YOUR FACE AND YOUR BREASTS.
- YOU'RE SO UNLIKE
YOUR BROTHER.
- OH, THANK YOU.
- GOB IS LIKE THE COCK
OF THE WALK, BUT NOT YOU.
- YOU'RE SO KIND.
- YOU'RE SENSITIVE,
LIKE A WOMAN.
- THAT'S ENOUGH.
WE DO HAVE TO DO
THE RIGHT THING.
- AND BEING TOGETHER
IS THE WRONG THING.
- VERY, VERY...
WRONG.
- [singing] AND IT'S THERE
WHEN YOU CALL OUT MY NAME
TWO, ONE, TWO,
THREE, FOUR
FIVE, SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT
LOVE, NINE, TEN, TWELVE
- IS THAT GOB?
- HE LIKES
TO MAKE LOVE TO THIS.
- I'M GONNA TURN THIS OFF.
- PLEASE.
- OH!
- GOB'S WAND.
- OH, THIS--
THIS IS SO WRONG.
- YES.
- NO, NO, NO.
- NOT--NOT--NOT--
NOT HOT WRONG.
YOU KNOW, REGULAR WRONG.
I GOT TO TELL GOB.
- NO, I HAVE TO TELL HIM.
- YES, BUT--BUT YOU SPEAK
A LITTLE SLOWLY,
AND I REALLY WANT
TO GET THIS THING MOVING ALONG.
SO, LISTEN,
YOU DO THE NOBLE THING,
AND YOU TELL HIM
THAT YOU'VE MET SOMEBODY ELSE.
I'M GONNA DO THE NOBLE THING
AND TELL HIM THAT IT'S ME.
WHILE I'M DOING MY NOBLE THING,
YOU COULD PUT THOSE PHOTOS
IN A BOX, GET RID OF THE WAND,
AND WE CAN DO THE WRONG THING
THE RIGHT WAY.
narrator:
AND MAEBY WAS GETTING TIRED
OF HER PARENTS'
CONSTANT FIGHTING.
- I'M SAYING EVERY
TIME SOMETHING STARTS
TO GO WELL FOR YOU,
YOU BLOW IT.
- NOTHING HAS EVER GONE WELL
FOR ME, AND YOU KNOW THAT!
- THAT'S MY POINT,
YOU HANDSOME COWBOY, YOU.
- OH, GREAT,
AND NOW YOU'RE MOCKING ME,
YOU SELFISH,
COUNTRY-MUSIC-LOVING LADY.
HELLO, MAEBY.
- NICE COVER.
WHY DON'T YOU TWO
JUST GET A DIVORCE
AND SAVE US ALL
A LOT OF GRIEF?
narrator: THE NIGHT BEFORE,
TOBIAS AND LINDSAY
HAD CHOSEN
TO SLEEP IN SEPARATE ROOMS,
AND TOBIAS HAD DROPPED AN
INTRIGUING BIT OF INFORMATION.
- AND THEN, OF COURSE,
WE COULDN'T CONCEIVE,
SO THERE WAS THAT FAMOUS ORDEAL.
- WHAT--WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU COULDN'T CONCEIVE?
[phone ringing]
WAS MAEBY ADOPTED?
IS SHE NOT REALLY RELATED TO ME?
IS SHE JUST SOME GIRL I KNOW?
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
NEVER GOT AN ANSWER.
- [whispering]
IT'S CARL WEATHERS.
narrator: SO HE SET ABOUT DOING
SOME INVESTIGATING ON HIS OWN.
- HEY, HAVE YOU EVER SEEN ANY
PICTURES OF YOUR MOM PREGNANT?
- DON'T TALK TO ME ABOUT MY MOM.
SHE'S CRAZY.
BOTH OF THEM ARE.
SOMETIMES I WISH
WE WEREN'T EVEN RELATED.
- HEY, YOU KNOW,
MAYBE WE'RE NOT.
BECAUSE, I MEAN,
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT IT,
WE DON'T EVEN REALLY
LOOK LIKE EACH OTHER.
- NO, I WAS TALKING
ABOUT MY PARENTS.
GOD, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THIS FAMILY?
- MAYBE WE'RE NOT A FAMILY.
AND MAYBE THAT'S
VERY, VERY RIGHT.
WE--
UNCLE GOB.
HEY, UH, WAS AUNT LINDSAY
EVER PREGNANT?
- OH, YEAH, DOZENS OF TIMES.
HEY, IS YOUR DAD AROUND, OR--
- HEY, GOB.
MARTA CALL?
- SHE SURE HAS--
FOUR TIMES,
BUT I DIDN'T TAKE THE CALLS.
- OH, NO?
WHY NOT?
- BECAUSE OF YOU.
YOU SAID TO LAY LOW.
AND IT'S WORKING.
- GREAT.
- TELL YOU WHAT,
YOU MAY NOT BE GOOD WITH WOMEN,
BUT YOU ARE GREAT
WITH OTHER PEOPLE'S WOMEN.
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT.
- LISTEN, GOB,
YOU CAN'T JUST IGNORE HER.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD TALK TO HER.
SHE IS YOUR GIRLFRIEND.
- EXACTLY.
AND I WANT TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
FOR ALL I KNOW, SHE'S CALLING
TO BREAK UP WITH ME.
I DON'T ANSWER THE PHONE,
THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN.
AND IT'S ALL BECAUSE
OF YOU, FRATELLO.
IT'S ITALIAN FOR BROTHER, SO...
NOW ALL I GOTTA DO
IS FIND THIS HERMANO GUY.
I'M GONNA KILL HIM.
- HEY, BROTHER.
- HEY, BUSTY.
- OH, HEY, BROTHER.
- HEY, BUSTER.
- GOB, THERE'S NO NEED
FOR VIOLENCE--THERE NEVER IS.
I LIKE TO THINK THAT WE'RE ALL,
YOU KNOW, INTELLIGENT,
MATURE, UM--
ADULTS THAT--THAT
CAN SETTLE THEIR DIFFERENCES,
WHENEVER THEY MIGHT COME
TO LIGHT, THROUGH WORDS.
- YEAH, WELL, I LET MY FISTS
DO THE TALKING.
NOT THIS ONE,
'CAUSE OBVIOUSLY,
I NEED IT
FOR COIN TRICKS AND STUFF.
BUT THIS ONE, I LET IT
SPEAK FOR BOTH OF THEM.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
MOM ALWAYS TAUGHT US
TO CURL UP IN A BALL
AND REMAIN MOTIONLESS
WHEN CONFRONTED.
THAT'S WHAT I DID IN HIGH SCHOOL
WHEN I ALMOST GOT INTO A FIGHT.
- I THINK THAT WAS ABOUT
BEING ATTACKED BY BEARS.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
- HEY, RICH KID.
GIVE ME YOUR LUNCH MONEY.
- BUT SOMETIMES I WONDER
WHAT IT WOULD BE LIKE
TO GET INTO A FIGHT TODAY.
- WELL, YOU'D BE
A MUCH BIGGER BALL.
- I MEAN,
THERE IS SO MUCH IN LIFE
THAT I HAVE NOT EXPERIENCED.
AND NOW THAT I'M AWAY FROM MOM,
I FEEL LIKE THIS IS
MY CHANCE TO LIVE.
I WANT TO DANCE.
I WANT TO MAKE LOVE TO A WOMAN.
I WANT TO GET
A CHECKING ACCOUNT.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT IT FEELS
LIKE TO GET MY FACE SOCKED IN.
[phone rings]
- MICHAEL, DON'T GET THAT!
THAT COULD BE MARTA!
- WHAT?
OOP.
TOO LATE.
HELLO?
- MICHAEL?
- OH, HI, MOM.
- I'M NOT HERE.
- IS THAT BUSTER?
TELL HIM I'M FINE WITHOUT HIM.
WHY HAVEN'T YOU CALLED ME BACK?
I'M WORRIED ABOUT
YOUR FATHER'S HEARING.
- MOM, LISTEN,
IT'S GONNA BE FINE.
I'M ON IT, OKAY?
I'M TAKING CARE OF IT.
I'LL BE THERE
FIRST THING FRIDAY MORNING.
- IT'S TOMORROW AT 4:30.
- OH, I SHOULD WRITE THAT DOWN.
- WHERE IS YOUR HEAD, MICHAEL?
- LISTEN,
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE FINE.
THEY JUST READ THE CHARGES,
AND WE LOOK LIKE A LOVING FAMILY
FOR, LIKE, SIX MINUTES.
- TEN MINUTES.
- WE COULDN'T
GET THAT DOWN, HUH?
narrator:
GEORGE MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
WENT TO SPEAK WITH TOBIAS.
- THIS WAS JUST FAXED TO YOU.
- OH, GREAT!
THE REWRITE.
LET'S SEE IF THEY'VE
BEEFED UP MY PART.
I GOT THREE LINES!
- SO, UH, I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT THAT, UH--
THAT CONVERSATION
WE WERE HAVING THE OTHER NIGHT
ABOUT, UH, WHERE MAEBY
CAME FROM, AND, UH,
I WAS JUST WONDERING IF
YOU COULD FINISH THAT THOUGHT.
- YES, OKAY.
UH, WELL, HAVE A SEAT.
UH...
UM...
WHEN A MAN
NEEDS TO PROVE TO A WOMAN
THAT HE'S ACTUALLY--
WHEN A MAN LOVES A WOMAN
AND HE ACTUALLY WANTS
TO MAKE LOVE, UH, TO HER,
SOMETHING VERY,
VERY SPECIAL HAPPENS.
AND, UH, WITH DEEP, DEEP
CONCENTRATION,
AND--AND GREAT FOCUS, HE'S OFTEN
ABLE TO ACHIEVE AN EREC--
- I'M SORRY.
I'M GONNA STOP YOU.
I KNOW WHERE YOU'RE, UH...
I-I DIDN'T MEAN
BABIES IN GENERAL.
- OH, WELL, THAT'S GOOD,
'CAUSE IT WAS ABOUT
TO GET A LITTLE, UGH, GROSS.
- YEAH, NO, I MEANT
SPECIFICALLY WITH MAEBY.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
THIS ISN'T RIGHT.
- I KNOW, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
- NO, NO.
IT SAYS IT'S A SHOWER SCENE.
I'M NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE IN A SHOWER SCENE.
IT HAS NUDITY.
narrator:
TOBIAS WAS A NEVER-NUDE,
WHICH IS
EXACTLY WHAT IT SOUNDS LIKE.
- I DON'T DO NUDITY.
IT SAYS THAT RIGHT ON MY RESUME.
OKAY, WHAT DO YOU THINK
I WEAR THESE FOR?
- I WAS NEVER ACTUALLY
CLEAR ON THAT.
- SO, YOU'RE, UH--
YOU'RE NOT WITH MARTA ANYMORE?
- WELL, MY PLAN IS TO
GET HER WANTING ME BUT BAD,
AND THEN I SPRING IT ON HER.
I KNOW YOU'VE
BEEN CHEATING ON ME,
AND YOU JUST
COST YOURSELF ONE FINE MAN
AND ONE FINE CD OF HIM SINGING
"LOVE IS IN THE AIR."
- WELL, I WOULD NEVER, UH,
DO THIS WHILE YOU WERE
STILL GOING OUT, BUT, UH,
IF YOU'RE DONE WITH HER,
I'D SURE LIKE A CRACK AT HER.
- [chuckling] RIGHT, RIGHT.
THAT SOUNDS GREAT.
GO FOR IT, BUDDY.
BUT YOU KNOW THAT SHE'S KIND OF
USED TO BEING WITH ME, RIGHT?
SO, IT'D BE SORT OF LIKE
GOING FROM PRIME RIB TO--
I DON'T KNOW--
WEIRD BROTHER OF PRIME RIB.
DO YOU EVEN KNOW HER?
- I MET HER.
I FELL FOR HER.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING HER PROGRAM,
"EL AMOR PROHIBIDO,"
THE LOVE THAT IS FORBIDDEN.
SHE IS THE LOVE
THAT'S FORBIDDEN.
THE LOVE OF MY HERMANO.
- WAIT A SECOND.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW HERMANO?
- "HERMANO" IS "BROTHER"
IN SPANISH.
AS IN, "HEY, HERMANO."
- BROTHER?
HERMANO MEANS BROTHER?
- YEAH.
- WELL, SOUNDS LIKE HERMANO
IS ABOUT TO GET HIS ASS KICKED.
- WELL, THIS IS WHAT
I SAID I WANTED.
SO, ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET IT OVER WITH.
[giggles, clears throat]
UH, SO,
ARE YOU GONNA HIT ME?
- NO, I'M NOT GONNA HIT YOU.
YOU'RE NOT THE BROTHER
MARTA'S CHEATING ON ME WITH.
- OH.
OH, WHO IS?
- HOW THE HELL
SHOULD I KNOW, BUSTER?
- YOU KNOW, THERE IS A GUY
WHO PLAYS HER OLDER BROTHER
ON HER SHOW.
I THINK HIS NAME IS TIO.
- TIO.
WELL, SOUNDS LIKE SOMEONE
WHO YOU THINK'S NAME IS TIO
IS ABOUT TO GET
HIS ASS KICKED.
THANKS FOR THE TIP, BUSTER.
- ALL RIGHT, MOM,
I'LL BE SURE TO TELL BUSTER.
RIGHT.
BYE.
MOM WANTED ME TO TELL YOU
THAT SHE DOESN'T CARE
WHETHER YOU LIVE OR DIE,
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT DEAD,
SHE WOULD LIKE TO SEE YOU
AT THE COURTHOUSE TOMORROW
IN THE BLUE SWEATER.
- DAMN IT!
I HATE THE BLUE SWEATER.
- SHE SAID IT WOULD LOOK NICE
WITH THE GRAY PANTS.
- DAMN IT!
SHE'S RIGHT!
- WHERE'S GOB?
- I THINK HE'S HEADING DOWN TO
THE SET OF MARTA'S SOAP OPERA.
- WHAT?
- GET THIS:
SHE MAY BE CHEATING ON HIM
WITH THE GUY
WHO PLAYS HER BROTHER.
I MEAN, I STILL LIKE HER,
BUT WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO DEAL WITH THIS.
- I GOTTA GO STOP HIM.
- AND I'VE GOT
A BLUE SWEATER TO STEAM.
- GOOD LUCK.
- THANKS.
narrator:
GOB RACED TO CONFRONT TIO,
WITH MICHAEL IN HOT PURSUIT.
GEORGE MICHAEL, HAVING FAILED
TO GET THE INFORMATION
HE NEEDED FROM ANYONE ELSE,
MADE THE ULTIMATE SACRIFICE
AND WENT TO THE KEEPER
OF THE FAMILY SECRETS.
- SO, UH, IT'S ABOUT MAEBY.
- OH, THAT'S A LOST CAUSE.
BUT YOU GET
WHAT YOU PAY FOR, HUH?
- YEAH.
WAIT, WHAT--WHAT--
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "PAY"?
- FERTILITY TESTS, LAB FEES,
DONORS, AND IMPLANTS.
SHE'S NOT REAL.
SHE WAS MADE IN A CUP.
LIKE SOUP--
A $130,000 CUP OF SOUP.
HOW DO YOU LIKE THEM
EGG ROLLS, MR. GOLDSTONE?
ALL I KNOW IS
IT TOOK AN EXTRA YEAR
BEFORE WE COULD ADD A DEN.
- SO ARE YOU SAYING WE'RE
NOT DIRECTLY RELATED?
- I'M SAYING SHE ALREADY SPENT
HER INHERITANCE GETTING HERE.
narrator: GOB, MEANWHILE,
HAD FINALLY SHOWN UP
AT THE "EL AMOR PROHIBIDO" SET.
- [speaking Spanish]
- HEY, GUY.
THEY TELL ME YOU'RE THE ACTOR
WHO PLAYS MARTA'S BROTHER, TIO.
- COMO?
- OH, YOU'RE GONNA BE
IN A COMA, ALL RIGHT.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
THE ACTOR WHO PLAYED TIO
HAD ALSO STARRED
IN A MEXICAN FILM
ABOUT THE LIFE
OF OSCAR DE LA HOYA.
- GOB, HEY.
- [gasps]
- HEY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
- WHERE AM I?
AM I IN 2/3
OF A HOSPITAL ROOM?
- YEAH, LISTEN, UM--
[sighs] IT'S ME.
I'M THE GUY THAT SHE LIKES.
"HERMANO" IS BROTHER.
ME.
- WELL, IF I'D KNOWN IT WAS YOU,
I WOULDN'T HAVE MINDED.
- YOU WOULDN'T?
- MICHAEL, YOU'RE A GREAT GUY.
IF YOU LIKED HER,
I WOULD HAVE SAID, "GO FOR IT."
- I DO KIND OF LIKE HER.
- GO FOR IT.
- HI.
MY BROTHER SAID WE CAN DO IT.
THAT DIDN'T COME OUT
AS ROMANTIC AS I'D HOPED, BUT--
["Love is in the Air" playing]
- EVERYTHING IS FINALLY PERFECT.
[phone ringing]
- OH, WAIT.
YOU JINXED IT.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL TURN IT OFF.
MM.
IT'S JUST MY MOTHER.
SHE'S PROBABLY WORRIED
ABOUT MY DAD'S HEARING.
- OH, WITH MY DAD,
IT IS THE VISION.
narrator:
MEANWHILE, TOBIAS TOLD LINDSAY
THAT HE COULDN'T DO THE PART.
- IT PLAYS NAKED, OKAY?
- TOBIAS, WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO DEAL WITH THIS SOMETIME.
I MEAN, I UNDERSTAND YOU NOT
WANTING TO DO IT ON FILM,
BUT YOU CAN'T EVEN GET
UNDRESSED IN FRONT OF ME.
- IT IS NOT YOU, LINDSAY.
I CAN'T GET UNDRESSED ALONE.
I CAN'T GET UNDRESSED
BY MYSELF.
I MEAN,
THIS IS A REAL AFFLICTION.
YOU KNOW, I'M SORRY IT'S NOT
RECOGNIZED HERE IN THE STATES.
BUT I KNOW FOR A FACT
THAT THERE ARE TWO MEMBERS
OF GERMAN PARLIAMENT.
THEY'RE CALLED
"NEIN WOHLSTANDIG" NUDE.
BUT THEY'RE GERMAN, SO--
I MEAN, THEY SPEAK GERMAN,
SO THEY HAVE A DIFFERENT--
- YEAH, WELL, IT'S NOT NORMAL,
AND IGNORING IT ISN'T
GONNA MAKE IT GO AWAY.
YOU'VE GOT NOTHING
TO BE ASHAMED OF.
- PLEASE...
PLEASE DON'T MAKE FUN.
- I'M NOT MAKING FUN.
LOOK, HOW ABOUT
WE DO THIS TOGETHER?
YOU TAKE OFF YOUR SHIRT,
AND I'LL TAKE OFF MY JACKET.
- YOU KNOW, THIS FAMILY CAN BE
PRETTY SCREWED UP SOMETIMES.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS IS--
- ACTUALLY,
I USED TO THINK THAT, TOO,
BUT IT'S BETTER
THAN THE ALTERNATIVE.
- WELL, HAVE YOU EXPLORED
ALL THE ALTERNATIVES?
'CAUSE I GUESS
WHAT I'M GETTING AT IS--
- NO, BUT I'M GLAD I HAVE
THIS FAMILY, YOU KNOW?
'CAUSE I KNOW I SAID SOME
BAD STUFF,
BUT IT'S MUCH BETTER
HERE THAN IT WAS IN BOSTON.
AND I HAVE A COUSIN HERE.
SO EVEN IF MY PARENTS DO GET
DIVORCED, I HAVE YOU, RIGHT?
narrator:
GEORGE MICHAEL REALIZED
THAT NO MATTER HOW MUCH
IT UPSET HIM,
HE DIDN'T WANT TO TAKE
MAEBY'S FAMILY AWAY FROM HER.
- YEAH, YOU GOT US, ALL RIGHT.
- NOW ALL I NEED
IS A BOYFRIEND.
narrator:
LUCILLE WAS LEFT ALONE
WITH HER OLDEST SON
AT THE COURTHOUSE.
- WELL, JUST YOU AND ME, HUH?
GOD, WHY AM I THE ONLY ONE
WHO EVER COMES THROUGH
IN THIS FAMILY?
narrator: AND GEORGE SR.
WAS LED INTO THE COURTROOM.
- WHERE THE HELL IS EVERYBODY?
- I'M HERE, DAD.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE NO ONE
SHOWED UP.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE IT'S FOR THE BEST.
MAYBE--MAYBE I SHOULD
JUST STAY IN PRISON
SO MY FAMILY CAN BE FREE.
- LOOK, YOU'RE MY HUSBAND, AND
YOU BELONG BACK AT HOME WITH ME.
- WOW.
YOU REALLY LOVE ME.
- CALL IT WHAT YOU WANT.
I'M TIRED OF PAYING LUPE
TO CLEAN ONE DISH.
- I'M SORRY, SORRY.
I'M SO LATE.
[pants] I HAD ANOTHER HEARING.
HERE'S THE GOOD NEWS:
I THINK I'M GONNA GET OFF, HUH?
I HAVE A GOOD LAWYER.
[smacks]
YOU LOOK GREAT IN RED.
OKAY.
ANYHOO, WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
WHAT'S THE PLAN?
- THE PLAN?
YOU'RE OUR LAWYER.
- IT'S A FIGURE OF SPEECH.
YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
HE'S ON HIS OWN FOR TWO DAYS,
AND HE JOINS A GANG.
- THESE GUYS?
OH, I'VE GOT THEM
FOR THE AFTERNOON.
BESIDES, THEY'RE THE ONLY THING
I HAVE LEFT
TO LIVE FOR IN THIS WORLD.
- OH, STOP BEING SO DRAMATIC.
YOU KNOW WHERE I LIVE.
- I WASN'T TALKING
ABOUT YOU, MOM.
I WAS TALKING ABOUT MARTA.
EXCUSE ME.
- WAIT, YOU WERE SERIOUS?
'CAUSE I GOT NEWS FOR YOU, PAL.
MARTA'S BEEN INTERESTED
IN MICHAEL.
THAT'S RIGHT--DULL,
NOTHING-GOING-ON-UPSTAIRS
MICHAEL.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
I SAW THEM MAKING OUT
AT HER FRONT DOOR.
- WHAT?
WHEN?
- JUST NOW.
HUH!
THE STUFF I'VE GOT
TO WORK OUT WITH MARTA
JUST KEEPS PILING UP.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
- ALL RISE.
THIS COURT IS NOW IN SESSION,
THE HONORABLE LIONEL PING
PRESIDING.
- [whispering] OH!
WE'VE GOT PING.
- I WOULD REMIND YOU
THAT THERE ARE NO CAMERAS
ALLOWED IN MY COURTROOM.
CONSPIRACY, RACKETEERING,
EVIDENCE TAMPERING,
FRAUD, THEFT,
GRAND THEFT, PETTY THEFT--
- WOW.
I-I-I DID NOT GET THAT PAGE.
- RESISTING ARREST...
- MICHAEL.
- RESISTING ARREST
AT THE SCENE.
- HOW DARE YOU!
- NOW, COME ON.
YOU SAID IT WAS OKAY.
AND NOTHING HAPPENED.
- NO.
- TAKE IT EASY, ALL RIGHT?
[gavel raps]
- ORDER!
- IS THAT MY BELT?
- WELL, SO WHAT?
- GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
- WHAT IS YOUR PROBLEM?
[all shouting]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
GET OFF HIM!
GEORGE!
narrator: GEORGE SR.,
HAVING NEVER HEARD HIS CHARGES
LISTED CONSECUTIVELY
IN ONE SITTING,
PANICKED AND RAN
WITH GREAT INTENSITY.
MICHAEL AND GOB
CONTINUED THEIR FIGHT
ONTO THE COURTHOUSE STEPS.
- STOP IT BEFORE SOMEONE
GETS HIT IN THE FACE!
narrator: BUSTER REALIZED
THIS WAS HIS OPPORTUNITY
TO FULFILL
A LONGTIME FANTASY.
- [growling]
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE!
BARRY!
narrator: BARRY, TOO,
FELT OVERWHELMED
BY THE CHARGES
LEVELED AGAINST HIS CLIENT
AND ALSO TOOK FLIGHT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THEY'LL ADD TEN YEARS
TO YOUR SENTENCE.
- THEY'LL NEVER CATCH ME!
- OH, GOOD.
WE BETTER GET YOU
BACK IN YOUR CELL.
IT'S GETTIN' KIND OF CRAZY
OUT THERE.
narrator:
AND BACK AT THE MODEL HOME,
THINGS WERE HEATING UP
FOR LINDSAY AND TOBIAS AS WELL.
- I CAN'T,
I CAN'T, I CAN'T, I CAN'T.
- FOR ME, TOBIAS.
THAT TOO.
YOU DID IT.
- NOW WHAT?
- NOW THIS.
narrator:
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME IN YEARS,
LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
BECAME INTIMATE.
THE BROTHERS' FIGHT, MEANWHILE,
CONTINUED INTO THE PARK,
WITH BUSTER STILL HOPING
TO TAKE A PUNCH.
- I'LL KILL YOU!
- OH, GOD!
- GO, GO, GO, GO!
narrator: LUCILLE
HAD DECIDED THAT PERHAPS
SHE WAS BETTER OFF
WITHOUT ANY OF THEM.
- ME! ME, ME, ME!
- BUSTER, GET OUT OF THE WAY!
- HIT ME IN THE FACE!
HIT ME IN THE FACE!
PLEASE!
- NO, BUSTER!
- AAH, BUSTER!
- narrator: WHILE MARTA,
WHO'D BEEN TOLD THE HEARING
WOULD LAST 10 MINUTES,
GOT TIRED OF WAITING.
- HEY!
HEY!
- MARTA.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE GOOD PEOPLE.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE NOBLE.
I-I-I THOUGHT YOU CARE ABOUT
FAMILY, BUT YOU CLEARLY DON'T.
I-I-IT'S OVER.
BOTH OF YOU.
IT'S OVER.
- WAIT, WAIT.
WHAT ABOUT--WHAT ABOUT ME?
- I'M SORRY, I'M NOT
TOTALLY SURE WHO YOU ARE.
- WOW!
WOW.
THAT'S WHAT IT FEELS LIKE
TO GET PUNCHED IN THE FACE.
- CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
- YEAH,
LECTURING US ABOUT FAMILY.
- I MEAN, WHO NEEDS THAT?
- AND WHAT ARE WE DOING?
HEY, WE'RE BROTHERS.
THAT'S GOT TO COUNT
FOR SOMETHING.
- THAT COUNTS FOR EVERYTHING.
- I'M NOT GONNA THROW IT AWAY
OVER SOME WOMAN.
- [chuckling]
ESPECIALLY NOT MY WOMAN.
BUT YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I MEAN, THIS IS WHAT'S REAL.
THIS IS WHAT LASTS.
EVERYTHING ELSE IS JUST PETTY.
- YEAH, TOTALLY BENEATH US.
- YEAH.
- AND BY THE WAY, I DON'T KNOW
HOW YOU CALL HER YOUR WOMAN
WHEN SHE CLEARLY PREFERS ME,
AND SHE WAS ALL PREPARED
TO BE MY GIRLFRIEND,
CALLING ME HER BOYFRIEND--
- WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HEY!
- HANG ON ONE SECOND.
- NO, NO.
FIRST OF ALL, THIS IS ALL MOOT,
BECAUSE SHE
NEVER GOT A CHANCE TO KNOW ME.
NOW, WILL SOMEONE
PLEASE HAVE THE DECENCY
TO PUNCH ME IN THE FACE?
AAH!
- WELL, IT'S EFFECTIVE.
- YEAH, IT REALLY IS.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
TOBIAS QUIETLY OVERCOMPENSATES.
- [yawning] PLEASE TELL ME
THERE'S SOME COFFEE LEFT.
[groans] GIVE ME SOME.
I SLEPT VERY WELL
LAST NIGHT.