narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL WAS SHARING HIS BED
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN YEARS.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT WAS WITH
HIS YOUNGER BROTHER, BUSTER.
- BUSTER.
BUSTER.
HEY-HEY.
WHOA, WHOA. BUSTER!
- HEY, BROTHER.
- [sighs]
I DON'T THINK US SLEEPING
TOGETHER IS WORKING OUT.
YOU'RE A GROWN MAN.
YOU SHOULD BE LIVING
WITH YOUR MOTHER.
- YEAH, I MISS MOM.
- I CAN TELL.
HEY, GOOD MORNING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- IT'S MY ETHICS ESSAY.
I'M SUPPOSED TO WRITE 200 WORDS
ON THE MORALITY OF WAR--
WHETHER A PREEMPTIVE STRIKE
IS EVER JUSTIFIED.
- ABSOLUTELY. IT'S PREEMPTIVE,
YOU KNOW,
HAPPENS BEFORE
SOMETHING ELSE, SO.
IF YOU CAN PREDICT AGGRESSION
AND YOU WANNA SQUASH IT--
I DON'T KNOW WHY
YOU'RE NOT TYPING?
THIS IS ALL GOOD.
- I'M NOT SURE
IF MY ETHICS TEACHER
WOULD LOVE
IF I CHEATED ON MY ESSAY.
- WELL, YOU JUST PASSED
MY ETHICS TEST.
narrator: IN FACT,
GEORGE MICHAEL HAD DEVELOPED
A HOPELESS CRUSH
ON HIS ETHICS TEACHER,
A WOMAN NAMED BETH BAERLY.
- EVEN MINOR CRIMES
ARE PUNISHABLE
BY BRUTALLY CHOPPING OFF
THE OFFENDER'S HAND.
- MMM. NO RING.
- CAN'T WAIT TO MEET HER
AT PARENT-TEACHER NIGHT.
- OH, YEAH. DAD, HEY, DAD,
TRY TO REMEMBER EVERYTHING
SHE SAYS ABOUT ME, ALL RIGHT?
- OKAY.
- MICHAEL.
I NEED YOU TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT MY SON.
- I TOTALLY AGREE, MOM.
BUSTER GOES HOME,
WE FLIP THE MATTRESS,
THIS NEVER HAPPENED.
- NOT BUSTER. READ THIS.
- DID YOU AND DAD
ADOPT A CHILD?
- THE S.E.C.
WAS ON TO US.
YOUR FATHER THOUGHT IT WOULD
MAKE US LOOK CHARITABLE.
HE MUST HAVE FORGED
MY SIGNATURE.
WELL, MAYBE I'LL GET A SON
WHO WILL FINISH
HIS COTTAGE CHEESE!
YOU'VE GOT TO GET ME
OUT OF THIS.
- I'LL CALL SOCIAL SERVICES,
BUT YOU MUST TAKE BUSTER BACK.
- OKAY.
- GREAT.
- BUT I'M NOT TAKING CARE
OF HIM EITHER.
I DON'T HAVE
THE MILK OF MOTHER'S KINDNESS
IN ME ANYMORE.
- YEAH, THAT UDDER'S BEEN DRY
FOR A WHILE NOW, HASN'T IT?
KIND OF?
[phone rings]
HELLO.
- MICHAEL.
I'VE GOT
A COUPLE OF GIRLS HERE.
A COUPLE OF FUN GIRLS
I THOUGHT
I'D BRING YOU IN ON.
- OH, I DON'T KNOW, GOB.
- COME ON, MICHAEL.
SO WE HAD A LITTLE DISAGREEMENT.
narrator: RECENTLY, GOB
HAD DISCOVERED
THAT MICHAEL WAS INTERESTED IN
HIS NOW EX-GIRLFRIEND, MARTA.
- I'M OFFERING YOU
AN OLIVE BRANCH HERE.
- YEAH-YEAH. NO. I-I KNOW.
AND I-I APPRECIATE THAT.
IT'S JUST THAT--
- BESIDES, WHEN WAS THE LAST
TIME YOU SLEPT WITH SOMEONE?
- BUSTER.
WHAT TIME AND WHERE?
- narrator: MEANWHILE, LINDSAY
WAS HELPING GEORGE MICHAEL
WITH HIS HOMEWORK.
- OH, COME ON,
LET'S DO SOMETHING.
IT'S JUST A STUPID ESSAY.
- NO, I CAN'T.
I DON'T WANT
TO LET DOWN MS. BAERLY.
SHE'S NICE, YOU KNOW.
AND SHE'S INTERESTING--
- AND PRETTY?
- WELL, I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M TELLING YOU THIS.
I GUESS
THERE'S JUST SOME THINGS
YOU CAN'T REALLY
SAY TO YOUR DAD.
- AH, SOUNDS LIKE YOU'D
LIKE HER TO BE MORE
THAN JUST YOUR TEACHER.
narrator: LINDSAY BELIEVED
THAT GEORGE MICHAEL
WANTED TO FIX UP HIS FATHER,
SO HE COULD FILL THE ROLE
OF HIS MOTHER.
- THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
ALTHOUGH, I MUST SAY
I'M A LITTLE HURT
THAT YOU HAVEN'T CONSIDERED ME.
- YOU'RE MY AUNT.
- [scoffs]
THAT DOESN'T MATTER.
AUNTS CAN FILL THAT ROLE.
TEACHERS CAN FILL THAT ROLE.
AND, SOMEDAY, YOU'RE GONNA FIND
THE RIGHT WOMAN
TO FILL THAT ROLE,
BUT UNTIL THEN. I'LL BE
RIGHT ACROSS THE HALL.
narrator: LINDSAY HAD NEVER
BEEN MORE PROUD
OF ANYTHING SHE HAD SAID
IN HER ENTIRE LIFE.
- YIKES.
narrator: MEANWHILE, GOB WAS
WAITING FOR MICHAEL TO SHOW UP.
- OH, THERE HE IS.
MICHAEL.
- YES.
- THIS IS SHANNON, THE GIRL
I'VE BEEN TELLING YOU ALL ABOUT.
- YES. GIRL, INDEED--
YOUNG GIRL.
THAT'S A YOUNG, YOUNG,
YOUNG, GIRL.
- YEAH, WELL, SHE'S 18.
SO, IT'S LIKE--
OH, AND THIS IS YOUR DATE,
NAZH--
- GALIA.
- HELLO, MY GOD!
- WELL, SHANNON WOULDN'T GO OUT
WITHOUT A CHAPERONE--
- RIGHT.
- AND SO SHE'S YOUR DATE.
narrator: IT WAS CLEAR
THAT GOB WASN'T OFFERING
AN OLIVE BRANCH AT ALL,
AND, IN FACT,
WAS STILL HARBORING
SOME RESENTMENT OVER MARTA.
- OH--[laughs]--NAGARMA,
YOU'VE GOT A MUSTACHE.
- HEY!
- I MEAN, YOU'VE GOT
MILK ON YOUR MUSTACHE.
- OH.
- [chuckles] I MEAN, YOU'VE GOT
A MILK MUSTACHE.
- YEAH.
IT'S ADORABLE.
YOU LOOK LIKE
ONE OF THOSE "GOT MILK" MODELS.
[men chuckling]
narrator: BUT GOB MISTOOK
MICHAEL'S BASIC HUMAN DECENCY
FOR ROMANTIC INTEREST
AND FELT A COMPETITIVE URGE
TO STEP IN.
- BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, IT'S BEYOND
ADORABLE AND E-EXOTIC.
I FIND YOU VERY ATTRACTIVE.
all: REALLY?
narrator: AND GEORGE SR. WAS
ABOUT TO GET A SURPRISE VISITOR.
- MR. BLUTH?
I'M CINDI LIGHTBALLOON.
I'VE STUDIED ALL YOUR TEACHINGS,
AND I'VE PURCHASED EVERY TAPE.
AND I WATCH 'EM
OVER AND OVER.
narrator: GEORGE SR.
HAD RECENTLY MARKETED
A LINE OF SELF-HELP TAPES,
TOUTING HIS NEWLY DISCOVERED
SPIRITUALITY.
- I'VE ALSO LOST FOUR POUNDS
ON YOUR LOW-CARB
BLUTH BANANA JAIL BARS.
[giggles]
I'VE COME TO LEARN
AT YOUR FEET.
- THAT'S A GOOD PLACE
TO START.
narrator: AND MICHAEL,
FREE OF HIS DOUBLE DATE,
MET LINDSAY
AT PARENT-TEACHER NIGHT.
- HEY, LINDS,
IS IT MY IMAGINATION
OR DOES THIS RAPE ROOM
HAVE THE SAME FLOOR PLAN
AS OUR KITCHEN?
- DID YOU MEET MS. BAERLY YET,
THE ETHICS TEACHER?
'CAUSE I JUST DID.
- NO, NOT YET.
LOOK, THESE ARE OUR CABINETS.
- YEAH. WELL, I THINK
SHE'S PERFECT FOR YOU.
- FOR ME? REALLY?
- MM-HMM.
- THANKS, BUT NO, LINDSAY.
I'VE ALREADY BEEN SET UP
ONCE TODAY BY A SIBLING,
AND I DON'T THINK
YOU PEOPLE KNOW MY TYPE.
- HEY, LOOK.
IT'S NOT COMING FROM ME.
IT'S-IT'S GEORGE MICHAEL.
HE TOLD ME.
I THINK HE WANTS A MOTHER.
- WELL, THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
HE'S GOT YOU.
HE'S GOT OUR MOTHER.
YOU'D THINK THAT WOULD TURN
HIM OFF TO THE ENTIRE CONCEPT.
BESIDES, I'M NOT GONNA RUSH OUT
AND MARRY SOMEBODY
JUST BECAUSE
YOU THINK MY SON WOULD LIKE IT.
- WELCOME.
I'M MS. BAERLY,
THE ETHICS TEACHER.
MY GOAL IS TO TEACH
YOUR CHILDREN
ABOUT THE PRECIOUSNESS OF LIFE
THAT CAN BE LOST BY THE MINDLESS
PULLING OF A TRIGGER.
- MMM. NO RING.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL GOT TO
KNOW HIS SON'S ETHICS TEACHER.
- ETHICS--
RIGHT AND WRONG.
- [chuckles]
- HOW CAN ONE THING CAN BE RIGHT
AND ANOTHER ONE BE WRONG?
I MEAN, WHICH IS WHICH,
YOU KNOW?
[both chuckling]
- I GUESS THAT'S
THE "RRRR" OF IT.
YOU KNOW,
SO FRUSTRATING.
- I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, THEY JUST THREW
THIS CLASS AT ME
AFTER MR. DANIELS
HAD A STROKE.
- [laughs]
I HAD HIM, MR. DANIELS.
HOW IS HE?
- OH, HE, YOU KNOW,
HAD A STROKE.
- OH.
THOUGHT THAT YOU WERE JOKING.
- NO, I WAS JUST LAUGHING
'CAUSE YOU WERE LAUGHING.
- RIGHT. NO.
YEAH. GOSH. HMM.
- YEAH.
- "RRRR!"
- [laughs] "RRRR!"
BUT, YOU KNOW, I-I-- I REALLY
AM ANTIWAR AND ANTIVIOLENCE.
- UH-HUH.
- AND I THINK
I'M AN ETHICAL PERSON.
- RIGHT.
HERE'S
AN ETHICAL QUESTION.
CAN-CAN A PARENT TAKE A TEACHER
OUT FOR A DRINK? OR--
- I DON'T KNOW.
UH, DO YOU HAVE A WIFE?
- YEAH.
BUT SHE'S DEAD.
- [laughs] OH.
[both laughing]
- [sucks teeth]
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN MARRIED?
- YEAH, SHE DIED.
- OHH.
GOD, WHY ARE WE LAUGHING?
- I DON'T-- WELL, IT'S THE
MR. DANIELS STROKE THING
ALL OVER AGAIN.
- [laughs]
- LET'S GO GET THAT DRINK.
- YEAH, IT COULD ONLY HELP.
- RRRR!
- [laughing]
RRR!
narrator: GEORGE SR. WAS DEALING
WITH HIS OWN ADMIRER.
- I'VE ALREADY TOLD
YOU SO MANY OF MY SINS.
MAYBE YOU COULD
TELL ME SOME OF YOURS.
- UH, WELL, THERE ARE
LEGAL IMPLICATIONS TO THAT.
BUT, UH, BACK TO YOUR SINS.
UH, DO THAT ONE ABOUT THE, UH,
[takes deep breath]
LADIES' SHOWER
IN YOUR COLLEGE DORM AGAIN.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
WAS ON HIS WAY
TO WHAT WOULD BE HIS SECOND DATE
WITH MS. BAERLY.
[ringing]
- MICHAEL,
THE LITTLE KOREAN IS HERE,
AND I DON'T KNOW WHAT
TO DO WITH HIM.
AT LEAST,
I THINK IT'S A HIM.
YOU GOT TO STRIP THEM
DOWN TO NEXT TO NOTHING
BEFORE YOU CAN EVEN TELL.
- YEAH, MOM.
I JUST SPOKE TO SOCIAL SERVICES,
AND ALTHOUGH
THEY DON'T LIKE TO DO THIS,
IF YOU CAN PROVE THAT IT'S A BAD
ENVIRONMENT FOR A CHILD--
AND I WOULD SUGGEST SAYING
WHAT YOU JUST SAID TO ME;
DON'T CHANGE A WORD--
THEY WILL TAKE HIM BACK.
- HA, HA, HA. UH,
DON'T GET TOO COMFORTABLE.
SHOES ON, MISTER!
SHOES ON!
HE'S OUT OF CONTROL.
[knocking]
HOLD ON.
- I'M BACK.
[rattling]
WHO'S THAT?
- THIS IS "ANNYONG," WHO YOUR
FATHER AND I HAVE ADOPTED.
- WHAT, I'M GONE FOR A COUPLE
DAYS AND YOU FIND A NEW SON?
narrator: LUCILLE COULD SEE
THAT HER SON WAS CONCERNED,
EVEN JEALOUS.
AND SHE KNEW HOW IT FELT
TO BE OVERLOOKED.
- YES.
ANNYONG IS YOUR BROTHER NOW.
- YES, ANNYONG.
EXCUSE ME.
OH, MICHAEL?
CALL IT OFF.
I'M KEEPING HIM.
- LOOK,
I GOTTA CALL YOU BACK.
- SWEET RIDE.
ARE YOU MAKING
DINNER RESERVATIONS?
- NO, NO.
THAT WAS MY MOM.
SHE JUST HAD
A LITTLE KOREAN DROPPED OFF.
- OOH, THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
LET'S HAVE THAT.
- HELLO.
- narrator:
AND AFTER THEIR DATE,
MICHAEL TOOK A STEP
HE HADN'T TAKEN IN YEARS.
- OKAY, DO YOU THINK
THIS IS A GOOD IDEA?
- I THINK
IT'S A GREAT IDEA.
- MMM.
SUCH A GOOD IDEA.
- BUT HOW ARE WE GOING TO SNEAK
IN WITHOUT WAKING EVERYONE UP?
- WE'LL TAKE THE STAIRS.
[stairs rumbling]
THIS MAY NOT HAVE BEEN
MY BEST IDEA.
- I'M SORRY, MICHAEL.
- I'M SORRY TOO, MICHAEL,
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE WE'RE EVEN.
YOU TOOK SOMETHING I LIKED.
I TOOK SOMETHING YOU LIKED.
YEAH.
I--[bleep] "NASHBAGERLAJAM."
- LISTEN,
I KNOW THAT YOU'VE BEEN
TRYING TO GET EVEN
WITH ME ABOUT MARTA.
BUT GOT BAD NEWS FOR YA.
I'M SEEING SOMEBODY ELSE.
- WHO? WHO?
JUST OUT OF CURIOSITY--
I'M NOT GONNA TRY
TO SLEEP WITH HER.
- FORGET IT. I THOUGHT
THAT THIS WAS BEHIND US.
- IT IS BEHIND US.
- GREAT.
- WHEN I SLEEP WITH HER.
'CAUSE I'M GONNA SLEEP WITH HER.
YEAH.
I WAS LYING WHEN I SAID I WASN'T
GONNA TO SLEEP WITH HER, SO--
- COURSE SHE'D HAVE
TO AGREE TO IT, GOB.
- OH, I DON'T ANTICIPATE
A PROBLEM WITH THAT, GUY.
- NO?
- NO.
'CAUSE I'VE SEEN
SOME OF THE DOGS THAT YOU LIKE.
- RIGHT.
- I JUST SLEPT WITH ONE.
- AGAIN,
DIDN'T LIKE NAZHGALIA.
- REALLY.
- REALLY, AND GOOD LUCK
GETTING RID OF HER.
- OH, PLEASE.
NOT A PROBLEM. SHE KNOWS IT WAS
A ONE-TIME THING. TOTALLY COOL.
[phone ringing]
- OH, SO ROMANTIC.
- WHO'S "N. BAHN-AHDEN?"
HELLO.
[sucks air]
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL.
I WANTED TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT
SOMETHING BEFORE,
BUT I DIDN'T
KNOW IF IT WAS REAL.
BUT NOW, UH,
YOUR ETHICS TEACHER--
- YEAH,
I JUST MADE THIS FOR HER.
- OH.
- SHE LOVES SADDAM HUSSEIN.
- I'M SURE SHE DOESN'T
LOVE SADDAM.
I'M SURE SHE IS INTERESTED IN
HIM AS A SUBJECT, YOU KNOW.
- RIGHT.
THAT'S WHAT I MEANT.
- GREAT.
- YOU KNOW, I JUST WANTED
TO MAKE HER SOMETHING SPECIAL
TO SHOW THAT I CARE.
- ABOUT THE CLASS?
- NO.
I MEAN, ABOUT HER.
- OH!
- I KIND OF LOVE HER.
- YOU MEAN, YOU LOVE HER LIKE--
LIKE SHE LOVES SADDAM, RIGHT?
- NO, NO. I MEAN, LIKE,
LOVE HER LOVE HER.
- OH.
[footsteps]
OH.
- OH, HI!
HI, GEORGE MICHAEL.
I WAS JUST LOOKING
AT THIS MODEL HOME.
I'M GONNA GO HOME
AND THINK ABOUT IT.
I'M GONNA GO HOME,
THINK ABOUT IT.
- DAD,
WHAT WAS SHE DOING HERE?
I MEAN, SH--
SHE WASN'T--
[door closes]
narrator: MICHAEL KNEW
HE HAD AN ETHICAL RESPONSIBILY
TO TELL HIS SON THE TRUTH.
- YES.
YOUR UNCLE GOB
SLEPT WITH HER.
- WELL, WHY WOULD HE DO THAT?
WHY WOULD GOB SLEEP
WITH MY ETHICS TEACHER?
- PROBABLY JUST
TO GET EVEN WITH ME.
- HOW WOULD THAT BE
GETTING EVEN WITH YOU?
I'M THE ONE
THAT LIKES HER.
- RIGHT. RIGHT.
NO, I KNOW.
YOU AND I KNOW THAT,
BUT GOB HE JUST--
HE'S NOT THAT-THAT
EXACT OF A TARGET SHOOTER,
AND HE JUST KIND OF
SPRAYS IT EVERYWHERE.
YOU KNOW, BUT LISTEN,
DID-DID YOU REALLY THINK
THAT-THAT--THAT YOU HAD A--
I MEAN, SHE'S KINDA OLD FOR YOU,
DON'T YOU THINK?
- WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
HOW OLD SHE IS.
NO ONE DOES.
SHE WAS CHAPERONING
THE DIVERSITY DANCE,
AND I THOUGHT,
LIKE, MAYBE AS A JOKE THING,
I'D GO UP
TO HER AND BE, LIKE,
"WELL, HEY,
DO YOU WANT TO DANCE?"
AND SHE'D BE, LIKE,
"AH, WHAT THE HECK?"
RIGHT?
OR SOME--I DON'T KNOW.
I DID IT DIFFERENTLY
IN THE MIRROR, BUT--
- RIGHT.
- BUT, YOU KNOW, LIKE, WE'D
BE JOKE DANCING OR SOMETHING.
- I GET IT.
- I DIDN'T THINK IT THROUGH.
- DON'T YOU THINK
YOU SHOULD BE TAKING
SOMEBODY YOUR OWN AGE
TO THE DANCE?
LIKE YOUR COUSIN.
THAT'S A BAD EXAMPLE, BUT--
- I FEEL SO STUPID.
I DEFACED A RARE BOOK
TO GET THAT PICTURE OF SADDAM
HUSSEIN IN A BATHING SUIT.
- "WHAT WOULD SADDAM DO?"
- YEAH.
YEAH, YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU'RE RIGHT. GOB'S GONNA PAY.
- OKAY, THAT IS OUR EXACT
OUTDOOR FIRE PIT.
narrator: AT PRISON, GEORGE SR.
WAS PREPARING FOR AN EVENING
WITH HIS MOST DEVOTED FAN.
WHILE CINDI LIGHTBALLOON WAS
MAKING PREPARATIONS OF HER OWN.
- HOW WE DOIN'?
- WE HAVE VIDEO.
- TESTING ONE, TWO.
- TILT BACK A LITTLE,
WILL YOU, HARRIS?
- LET'S BUST THIS GUY.
[blows smoke]
narrator: SO GEORGE MICHAEL,
STILL ANGRY AT GOB,
SOUGHT OUT THE FAMILY EXPERT
ON MAKING TROUBLE.
- I KNOW HE WAS DATING
THAT GIRL SHANNON.
- THE CHEERLEADER?
- YEAH, SHE'S PROBABLY
GONNA TAKE HIM
TO THAT STUPID DIVERSITY DANCE.
I WISH I HAD SOMEONE
SHOCKING TO TAKE.
YOU KNOW, I ACTUALLY CALLED
MR. DANIELS AND ASKED HIM,
BUT HE GOT ALL OUT OF BREATH
AND DROPPED THE PHONE.
I NEVER HEARD BACK.
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE--MAYBE
WE SHOULD GO TOGETHER.
RIGHT, I MEAN, IT'S A BAD
EXAMPLE--I--BUT SHOULD WE?
- HELLO.
- YES, ANNYONG.
YOUR NAME'S ANNYONG.
WE ALL KNOW YOU'RE ANNYONG.
ANNYONG. ANNYONG. ANNYONG.
- WHO'S THIS?
- OH, I'M SORRY.
THIS IS ANNYONG.
- MY MOM BOUGHT HIM.
SHE'S MAKING ME
REGISTER HIM FOR SCHOOL.
HE'S MY NEW LITTLE BROTHER.
- SO WE'RE RELATED.
HEY, DO WANNA GO TO A DANCE?
- OH, GREAT,
ANOTHER UNCLE TO COMPETE WITH.
narrator: AND MICHAEL WENT
TO DISCUSS THE GEORGE MICHAEL
SITUATION WITH MS. BAERLY.
- BEING HELD AGAINST THEIR WILL
[giggles]
PURELY ON THE BASIS OF
POLITICAL OR RELIGIOUS BELIEFS.
[giggling]
I'M SORRY.
I MET SOMEONE.
ANYWAY, THIS IS SERIOUS.
THIS IS ATROCITIES.
NO MORE SMILING.
[knocking]
MICHAEL!
UH, JUST A MINUTE.
- HI. SORRY.
- HI!
- DON'T WORRY.
GEORGE MICHAEL'S NOT IN THERE.
THOSE ARE DUMB KIDS.
- OKAY.
UM, LISTEN.
THIS IS UH--
- WOW!
DID YOU MAKE THIS FOR ME?
THIS IS SO SWEET.
I LOVE HUSSEIN.
- YOU MEAN, YOU'RE
INTERESTED IN HIM.
- OH, YES. HE IS A MONSTER.
- YEAH.
- WOW. WHERE DID YOU FIND
THIS ONE OF HIM IN A SPEEDO?
- THIS IS WHAT I WANT TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT, THOUGH.
UM, BETH, I DON'T THINK THAT
I CAN CONTINUE TO SEE YOU.
- [giggles]
BUT I'VE ENJOYED
MY TIME WITH YOU.
YOU EVER WANNA TALK ETHICS--
- YOU REALLY MEAN IT?
THIS ISN'T ONE OF
"MY WIFE DIED" JOKES?
- NO, I'M AFRAID
THIS IS SERIOUS.
- OH.
- YOU SEE, GEORGE MICHAEL
MADE THIS POSTER FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, HE-HE KIND OF, UH,
IS IN LOVE WITH YOU, SO--
- I MEAN,
HE KNOWS WE'RE GOING OUT.
HE SAW ME THIS MORNING.
- NO, I COVERED THAT.
I TOLD HIM THAT YOU
SLEPT WITH MY BROTHER.
- THAT MAY BE THE MOST UNETHICAL
THING I'VE EVER HEARD.
- WELL, YOU'VE ONLY BEEN DOING
THIS HALF A SEMESTER.
LOOK, IT WAS
A PREEMPTIVE STRIKE.
MY BROTHER WOULD'VE
TRIED TO SLEEP WITH YOU.
- WELL, I WANT YOU TO LEAVE
RIGHT NOW AND NOT COME BACK.
- RIGHT. I KNOW.
I UNDERSTAND. I'M SORRY.
AND YOU WILL NOT SEE ME AGAIN.
[bell rings]
STARTING RIGHT NOW.
narrator: GEORGE SR.
WENT ON A WALK WITH CINDI.
- GEORGE.
narrator:
AND SHE WAS GETTING TO HIM.
- YOU CAN FEEL SAFE TO FULLY
REVEAL YOURSELF TO ME.
- HMM, ALL RIGHT.
[sighs]
THERE IS--
THERE IS SOMETHING.
- COME CLOSER.
- [sighs]
IT'S WEIGHING HEAVY ON MY SOUL.
YOU, UH--YOU KNOW, THE TALMUD
TEACHES US TO--THERE YOU GO.
[inhales sharply]
- WHAT'S HE DOING?
- HE'S PINCHING
THE CAMERA.
- HE'S ON TO US.
HE'S FOUND THE CAMERA.
- GET OUT OF THERE. HE'S GOT
THE CAMERA. ABORT! ABORT!
- GET THE DOG. CLEAN THE DOG.
WE ARE CLEANING THE DOG!
- [moaning]
narrator: THAT NIGHT, BUSTER
CAME HOME TO AN EMPTY APARTMENT.
- SO, IT'S OFF
WITH MOTHER NOW.
narrator: IN FACT,
LUCILLE WAS JUST GIVG ANNYONG
AND MAEBY A RIDE.
- YOU'RE TRYING TO STEAL
FROM THE WRONG MAN.
WATCH YOUR BACK,
MY LITTLE IMMIGRANT FRIEND!
narrator: AND THE SPRING
DIVERSITY DANCE
WAS IN FULL SWING.
- WHOA, SORRY.
STUDENTS ONLY.
- OH.
SO YOU'RE NOT LETTING HIM IN
BECAUSE HE DOESN'T SHARE YOUR
PERFECTLY SHAPED NOSE,
YOUR ROUND EYE-SHAPED EYES,
YOUR STRONG SQUARE JAW.
- THANKS.
YOU WANNA DANCE?
- YEAH!
- ALL RIGHT!
- STEVE HOLT!
narrator: AND GOB SOUGHT OUT
SHANNON--
- SHANNON!
narrator: WHO HAD FOUND OUT
HE HAD CHEATED ON HER
WITH NAZHGALIA.
- SHANNON, WHERE ARE YOU?
SHANNON!
OH, HEY, LISA.
EXCUSE ME.
LOOK, I BLEW IT, OKAY?
BUT I BOUGHT A YEARBOOK AD
FROM YOU.
DOESN'T THAT MEAN
ANYTHING ANYMORE?
- BETH! HEY, HI.
LISTEN,
UM, I BLEW IT, OKAY?
I HAD TO SEE YOU.
I-I'VE BEEN GIVING THIS
A LOT OF THOUGHT,
AND-AND I HAVE
TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
- YOU'RE GONNA TELL
GEORGE MICHAEL THE TRUTH?
- OH, THAT'S--THAT'S YOUR
DEFINITION OF THE RIGHT THING.
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA MAKE
A BIG DRAMATIC ENTRANCE
AND TELL YOU
THAT I WANTED TO SEE YOU. OKAY.
UH, I'LL GET RIGHT ON THAT.
GEORGE MICHAEL!
WHERE ARE YOU?
- UNCLE GOB?
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
AT A HIGH SCHOOL DANCE?
- I'M LOOKING FOR YOU.
HOW COULD YOU DO THIS TO ME?
- DO WHAT?
I'M JUST HERE WITH MY GIRL.
- YEAH, MY ETHICS TEACHER.
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL.
- NO, DAD. I'M TAKING CARE
OF SOMETHING, OKAY?
YOU SLEPT
WITH MY ETHICS TEACHER.
[overlapping chatter]
- JUST HANG ON A SECOND.
IT WASN'T HIM.
IT'S ME, OKAY?
- WHA--
- I'VE BEEN DATING
YOUR ETHICS TEACHER.
- WOW, MICHAEL.
I'M REALLY TOUCHED THAT
YOU'D STICK UP FOR ME
AFTER I'VE BEEN
SO HORRIBLE TO YOU.
- HUH?
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
NOW IT'S TIME
FOR ME TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
I SLEPT WITH THE ETHICS TEACHER.
I'M SORRY.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- LINDSAY TOLD ME
THAT YOU LIKED HER,
AND I'M NOT PROUD OF THIS,
BUT I [bleep] MRS. WHITEHEAD.
narrator: IN FACT, GOB MISTOOK
THE CIVICS TEACHER
FOR THE ETHICS TEACHER
MICHAEL WAS DATING.
- MAN, HE HAS A TYPE.
- GOB, MRS. WHITEHEAD
WAS THE CIVICS TEACHER.
WE BOTH HAD HER.
- YES, WE HAVE.
AND NOW WE'RE EVEN.
- WHAT A PIG.
- TELL ME ABOUT IT.
- NO, YOU!
YOU'RE THE PIG!
TWO STRIKES.
YOU ARE OUT.
- LISTEN. SHANNON, PLEASE.
IT WAS A ONE-TIME THING.
I'M NOT GONNA EVEN
HEAR FROM HER AGAIN!
[ringing]
ACH!
[ringing continues]
WHO IS EDNA W.?
HELLO?
[groans]
- WHAT'S GOING
ON HERE, DAD?
- WELL, IT-IT-IT WAS ME, OKAY?
I-I'VE BEEN SEEING MS. BAERLY,
AND I SHOULD NEVER HAVE BROUGHT
GOB INTO IT.
BUT THAT DAY THAT YOU TOLD ME
YOU LIKED HER,
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT ELSE TO DO.
I NEVER WANTED TO HURT YOU.
- WELL, DIDN'T AUNT LINDSAY
TELL YOU THAT I LIKED HER?
- YEAH, SHE DID.
BUT SHE SAID THAT
YOU WANTED HER AS A MOTHER,
AND I SAID THAT WAS RIDICULOUS,
BUT THEN I MET HER
AND KIND OF FELL FOR HER
AND THOUGHT THAT SHE WOULD
KIND OF MAKE A GREAT MOTHER.
- IS THAT TRUE?
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE THAT SERIOUS.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
I'M OPEN TO IT.
WE'RE OPEN TO IT.
- WOW!
NO, NO, NO, NO.
- I'M JUST SAYING SOMEDAY,
YOU KNOW.
- I'M NOT REALLY INTO KIDS.
- I'M JUST--I'M NOT TRYING
TO RUSH ANYTHING.
- HEY!
THE LADY SAID NO, MAN.
- LOOK, MICHAEL, I HOPE YOU FIND
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
I MEAN WE HAD SOME LAUGHS
ABOUT SOME VERY SAD THINGS,
BUT I DON'T THINK
WE HAVE A FUTURE.
AND, JEREMY, I WILL
TAKE THAT CUPCAKE.
- OHH. OKAY, UM--
HEY, UH,
YOU WANNA DANCE?
- SURE, WHY NOT?
- I CAN'T BELIEVE THAT
WOULD HAVE WORKED.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT"...
BUSTER'S COMPETITION
HEATS UP.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
WE ARE NOT ALLOWED
TO HAVE CANDLES IN HERE.
MOM WOULD FREAK.
- OH, NO, IT'S FINE.
THIS IS AMERICA, BABY.
YOU PRAY HOW YOU WANT.
- [Buster scoffs]
I'LL LIGHT A CANDLE
OF MY OWN.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I'LL DO.
[alarm beeping]