narrator:
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL HAD BEGUN
TO WORK WEEKENDS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THIS INTERFERED
WITH THE SATURDAY MORNING
BIKE RIDE
HE USUALLY TOOK WITH HIS SON.
- SO THIS ISN'T BAD, RIGHT?
JUST LIKE A NORMAL SATURDAY.
YOU KNOW, DAD,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DRIVE SO SLOW.
I CAN RIDE MY BIKE
BY MYSELF.
- THIS ACTUALLY
DOESN'T GO ANY FASTER.
[phone ringing]
- I MEAN, I KNOW YOU HAVE
A LOT OF WORK, YOU KNOW?
- IT STILL DOESN'T MEAN
I CAN'T HANG OUT WITH MY--
HANG ON ONE SECOND.
THIS IS MICHAEL.
MOM, I'M EXPECTING
A VERY IMPORTANT PHONE--
FOR GOD'S SAKES!
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
- DAD. DAD!
[bike brakes screeching]
- NICE INSTINCTS, SON.
GOOD REFLEXES.
narrator: BACK AT
THE MODEL HOME,
LINDSAY AWOKE LATE
TO FIND HER HUSBAND MISSING.
- MAEBY? MICHAEL? TOBIAS?
WORK?
narrator: TOBIAS HAD RECENTLY
BEEN CAST IN A MOVIE,
PLAYING THE ROLE
OF A FRIGHTENED INMATE.
- I AIN'T GOING TO SQUEAL, MAN.
[scoffs]
I AIN'T GOING TO--
OH, I'M NOT FRIGHTENED! GOD!
LINDSAY, SAY SOMETHING
TO SCARE ME.
- [beep] ME.
- NOPE. NOTHING.
THANKS FOR TRYING, THOUGH.
YOU KNOW WHAT I OUGHT TO DO?
I OUGHT TO CHECK MYSELF
INTO A MEN'S PENAL COLONY.
PERHAPS YOUR FATHER
COULD GET ME IN.
- WELL, IF HE CAN GO TO WORK,
SO CAN I.
narrator: LUCILLE, MEANWHILE,
WAS GROWING CLOSER
TO HER RECENTLY ADOPTED
KOREAN SON,
WHOM SHE CALLED ANNYONG.
- MUCH BETTER, ANNYONG.
narrator: WHICH ISN'T A NAME,
BUT THE KOREAN WORD
FOR "HELLO".
- AND I GUESS I CAN
COMB MY OWN HAIR.
- OH, PLEASE.
HE'S A LITTLE BOY,
AND SINCE HE'S GOING TO GO OFF
AND WORK FOR 10 HOURS,
I WANT HIM TO LOOK NICE.
- THANK YOU, LUPE.
- YOU GOT A JOB, ANNYONG?
- ANNYONG.
- AT THE BANANA STAND.
OH, HIS WORK
ETHIC IS UNBELIEVABLE,
UNLIKE SOME SONS I KNOW.
- I'M A SCHOLAR.
I ENJOY SCHOLARLY PURSUITS.
- [sighs]
SUDDENLY PLAYING WITH YOURSELF
IS A SCHOLARLY PURSUIT.
- HEY, LUPE.
- [sighs]
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH LUPE?
- OH, SHE'S UPSET
BECAUSE I TOLD HER
SHE COULDN'T TAKE THE DAY OFF.
THERE'S A FAMILY REUNION
IN CATALINA.
- CATALINA? WE'RE NOT GOING
TO CATALINA, ARE WE?
narrator: BUSTER HAD
AN UNFORTUNATE ENCOUNTER
IN A PHOTO BOOTH
ON THE WILDLIFE-POPULATED
ISLAND OF CATALINA.
- NO, LUPE IS.
YOU SEE, FOR HER,
A FAMILY REUNION MIGHT ACTUALLY
BE A PLEASANT EXPERIENCE.
- THEY'VE GOT A BUS,
AND THEY WANT TO USE
THE PARKING LOT TO THIS BUILDING
AS A MEETING PLACE.
I MEAN, FOR GOD'S SAKE,
IT'S NOT A HARDWARE STORE.
WE CAN'T HAVE THEM
HANGING AROUND LIKE FREELOADERS,
LOOKING FOR AN EASY BUCK.
- WHAT'S THE EMERGENCY, MOM?
- I NEED MONEY.
- I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR THIS, OKAY?
I DON'T EVEN
GET TO SEE MY OWN SON.
I'M GOING TO GO TO WORK NOW.
- AND WHILE YOU'RE THERE,
FIND OUT FROM YOUR ASSISTANT,
KITTY, WHY SHE DIDN'T SEND
MY PAYCHECK.
- YOU GET A PAYCHECK
FROM THE BLUTH COMPANY?
- WELL, IT'S IMPORTANT
TO THE COMPANY
THAT I KEEP UP THE IMAGE
OF MY LIFESTYLE.
- ILLUSION, MOM.
AND I'M THE PRESIDENT
OF THAT COMPANY.
I BELIEVE I'M THE ONE
THAT ASKED YOU
TO START SHOPPING
AT QUANTITY PLUS.
- AND THEY MADE ME APPLY
FOR A MEMBERSHIP CARD.
IT WAS HUMILIATING.
- I'LL SEE WHAT
I CAN DO FOR YOU.
AND NOW THAT I KNOW THAT
I'M THE ONE THAT PAYS LUPE,
I'M GIVING HER
THE DAY OFF, OKAY?
LUPE, DID YOU HEAR THAT?
TELL YOUR BUS DRIVER
THAT HE CAN PICK UP YOUR FAMILY
AT THE BLUTH COMPANY
PARKING LOT.
- OH, THANK YOU, MICHAEL.
- MY HERO.
- ANYWAY, YOU ENJOY
THAT PAYCHECK WHEN YOU GET IT.
IT WILL BE THE LAST ONE
I EVER SEND HERE.
- DOES THAT MEAN I HAVE TO GO
TO YOUR OFFICE TO GET MINE, TOO,
OR HOW'S THAT WORK?
- YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT, BUSTER?
BOB, IN THE COPY ROOM,
HE QUIT TODAY.
IF YOU WANT YOUR MONEY,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
WORK FOR IT.
- OKAY. I ACCEPT.
I'LL TAKE THAT JOB.
I WILL WORK IN THE COPY ROOM.
- I WOULDN'T GO IN THERE
WITHOUT KNOCKING, MICHAEL.
- NOW, I KNOW WE'VE BEEN
PUTTING IN A LOT OF HOURS,
BUT WE'VE GOT TO KEEP OUR
HEADS DOWN AND POWER THROUGH,
YOU KNOW, AND--AND SACRIFICE.
- [chuckles]
DON'T MIND ME.
I'M JUST HERE TO PICK UP
MY PAYCHECK AND GET OUT OF HERE.
- GUYS, GO AHEAD
AND TAKE A THREE.
LINDSAY, HOW CAN YOU
JUST COME IN HERE
AND ASK ME FOR A PAYCHECK?
- WELL, I USUALLY ASK KITTY,
UH, BUT SHE'S NOT AROUND,
AND YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE HERE
I'VE EVER SEEN BEFORE.
- HOW LONG HAS THIS
BEEN GOING ON?
- DAD HIRED ME OUT OF COLLEGE.
- YOU QUIT COLLEGE.
- YEAH, WELL, I HAD A JOB.
WHAT WAS THE POINT?
- WELL, YOU HAVE A JOB NOW.
SINCE KITTY'S GONE,
YOU CAN EARN YOUR CHECK
BY ANSWERING THE PHONES.
- MICHAEL, IT'S FRIDAY.
EVERYBODY COASTS ON FRIDAY.
- IT'S ACTUALLY SATURDAY.
- FINALLY.
I'M OUT OF HERE.
I'LL SEE YOU TUESDAY.
- I'M SERIOUS, LINDSAY.
- THIS IS WHY
YOUR EMPLOYEES HATE YOU.
- THEY'RE ACTUALLY
QUITE FOND OF ME.
[toilet flushing]
- OKAY, GUYS,
BACK TO THE STAFF MEETING.
[groaning]
-UH, LINDSAY. HELLO.
THE PHONES.
-WELL, YOU SAID "STAFF."
THE ZONING COMMITTEE
FEELS THAT WE'RE
TRYING TO SQUEEZE TOO MANY UNITS
ONTO A LOT THIS SIZE,
AND OBVIOUSLY WE NEED TO
IF WE WANT TO MAKE A PROFIT.
SO HOW DO WE FIT
THESE UNITS ON THERE?
- ARE THESE FLUORESCENT LIGHTS
BOTHERING ANYBODY ELSE
BESIDES ME?
-THAT'S NOT WHAT
I WANT TO DEAL WITH TODAY.
- WELL, YOU AND I HAVE DIFFERENT
MANAGEMENT STYLES.
I BELIEVE WORK SHOULD BE FUN,
AND YOU TRY TO CRUSH
PEOPLE'S SPIRITS.
WHAT'S NEXT, MICHAEL?
ARE YOU GOING TO
MAKE DANCING ILLEGAL?
IS THIS THE TINY TOWN
FROM FOOTLOOSE?
[chuckling and mumbling]
- CAN YOU GO TO YOUR DESK,
PLEASE?
BE LIKE BUSTER.
HE'S BEEN IN THE COPY ROOM.
I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM ALL DAY.
narrator: IN FACT,
BUSTER HAD GROWN ANXIOUS
IN THE CONFINED SPACE
OF THE COPY ROOM.
- BOB?
- [gasps]
- [sheep bleating]
- BOB?
- [gasping]
- I NEED A DIFFERENT JOB.
I'M HAVING REAL TROUBLE
IN A CONFINED INDOOR SPACE.
OH. HEY, COWORKER.
- HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT WORKING OUTDOORS?
- UH, WHAT ELSE DO YOU HAVE?
narrator: AT THE BANANA STAND,
GEORGE MICHAEL WAS ALSO WORKING.
- I THOUGHT YOUR DAD
WORKED LAST WEEKEND.
- NO, LAST WEEK HE HAD TO FINISH
PLANNING THE NEW SUBDIVISION.
- OH. SO DID HE FINISH IT?
- NO. HEY, ARE YOU
TRYING TO MAKE ME FEEL BAD?
- YEAH, I GUESS. SORRY.
- YEAH.
- I'M JUST BORED.
- THAT'S OKAY.
- I GUESS HE JUST LIKES WORK
MORE THAN HE LIKES YOU.
narrator: AND TOBIAS
WENT TO THE PRISON
IN PREPARATION
FOR HIS OWN WORK.
- I HAVE A LETTER
OF INTRODUCTION HERE
FROM CARL WEATHERS.
narrator: FORTUNATELY,
THE NEW WARDEN
WAS AN APPRECIATOR OF THE ARTS.
- IT WOULD BE AN HONOR
TO HAVE YOU RESEARCH
IN THIS INSTITUTION.
- OH.
- AND, IF I MAY,
I HAVE THIS SCRIPT
I'D LOVE TO GET TO CARL.
- OKAY.
- THE WARDEN
COULD EASILY BE BLACK.
- OH! YES.
- OKAY.
LETS SEE, NOW.
187 WON'T BE FREE
TILL TUESDAY AT MIDNIGHT.
AND I CAN'T PUT YOU INTO 212,
BECAUSE THERE'S ALREADY
ANOTHER ACTOR
RESEARCHING A ROLE IN THERE--
STEVE BUSCEMI.
- OH! RE--
WELL, I--I WOULD LIKE TO BUNK
WITH MY FATHER-IN-LAW.
- OKAY.
LET'S GET YOU INTO WARDROBE.
- [chuckles]
WOW! PRISON!
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL AND BUSTER
HAD ARRIVED
AT THE CONSTRUCTION SITE,
AND BUSTER WAS ACTUALLY
STARTING TO ENJOY HIMSELF.
- MICHAEL,
I'M REINFORCING THE HEADER!
- THAT'S GREAT, BUDDY.
- [giggles]
- LISTEN, ALSO, I KNOW THAT
WE'RE BEHIND ON THE PAYROLL,
BUT AS SOON THE ZONING COMMITTEE
GIVES ME THEIR APPROVAL,
I KNOW THE BANK'S
GONNA RELEASE THE MONEY.
RIGHT NOW, I'M JUST
ASKING EVERYONE TO JUST,
YOU KNOW,
POWER THROUGH, SACRIFICE.
- I'LL TRY, BUT THESE GUYS
HAVE BEEN WORKING TOO HARD
NOT TO GET PAID.
- I'LL GET ON IT.
BUT UNTIL THEN, YOU KNOW,
I GOT BUSTER HERE TO HELP.
THAT'S ANOTHER GUY.
- [shouts and moans]
- MICHAEL.
MICHAEL.
- HOW'D YOU KNOW I WAS HERE?
- I CALLED THE OFFICE.
YOU KNOW, THAT KITTY
IS STARTING TO SOUND
PRETTY DAMN SEXY TO ME.
MAYBE I OUGHTA--
- THAT WAS LINDSAY.
- ANYWAY--
- YEAH.
- WHAT'S BUSTY DOING HERE?
- MICHAEL GOT ME THE JOB.
- HOW DID YOU GET HIM
TO DO CONSTRUCTION WORK?
THE GUY'S, LIKE,
THE WORLD'S BIGGEST CHICKEN.
[staccato cawing]
- I'M NOT A CHICKEN.
- YEAH, HE'S NOT A CHICKEN.
HE JUST DOESN'T LIKE
CONFINED SPACES; THAT'S ALL.
- I THOUGHT IT WAS OPEN SPACES.
- NO, IT'S BOTH,
BUT I LOVE IT HERE.
AND THE LANGUAGE
THESE GUYS USE--ROUGH!
ONE OF THE GUYS TOLD ME
TO TAKE MY HEAD OUT OF MY BOTTOM
AND GET BACK TO WORK.
[giggles]
MY BOTTOM!
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOU WANT YOUR PAYCHECK?
I USUALLY GET CASH
UNDER THE TABLE,
BUT IF YOU
MADE IT OUT TO CASH--
- WELL, I GOT BAD NEWS FOR YOU,
GOB.
[grunting]
- HEY, PICK UP THE PACE,
DOUCHE BAG!
- MICHAEL!
- YOU TOO, CANDY ASS!
- [giggles]
"CANDY ASS."
narrator: WITH MICHAEL GONE,
LINDSAY WAS TAKING OVER.
- THANKS, FELLAS.
WE, UH,
FINISHED THE PROPOSAL,
AND WE'RE GONNA
ORDER SOME PIZZA.
UM, WE WERE WONDERING
IF WE COULD HAVE TWO TOPPINGS
ON ACCOUNT IT'S SATURDAY.
- WELL, HE'S NOT HERE,
AND SINCE I'M IN CHARGE,
I'M TAKING YOU
ALL OUT TO LUNCH,
THE WHOLE STAFF.
- WE HAVE TO GO TO LUNCH!
- WE HAVE TO GO TO LUNCH,
YOU GUYS.
- COME ON.
LETS GO TO LUNCH.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO THE LIGHTS?
- ISN'T THIS BETTER?
DOESN'T THIS JUST
WANNA MAKE YOU CURL UP
AND FORGET ABOUT THE WORLD?
- LINDSAY, WE NEED THE LIGHTS
SO THAT PEOPLE--
WHERE ARE THESE PEOPLE GOING?
- I'M TAKING THEM OUT TO LUNCH.
- DID YOU RESERVE A RESTAURANT?
ARE THEY TAKING THEIR OWN CARS?
- OH, THEY'LL
FIGURE SOMETHING OUT.
- NO, THEY WON'T.
YOU DON'T HAVE A PLAN?
I TOLD YOU,
THESE PEOPLE ARE SHEEP.
ALL RIGHT?
AND THEY'LL WANDER OFF,
AND YOU'LL LOSE THE SHEEP.
YOU'VE LOST THE SHEEP.
- OH, THEY'LL BE FINE.
narrator: IN THE PARKING LOT,
THE EMPLOYEES BOARDED THE BUS
LUPE HAD RENTED
FOR HER FAMILY REUNION,
THINKING LINDSAY HAD RESERVED IT
TO TAKE THEM TO LUNCH.
- WELL, I NEED THIS PROPOSAL.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY CAN
WALK OFF AND JUST--
- IT'S RIGHT HERE, MICHAEL.
YOU WEREN'T HERE,
AND EVERYTHING GOT DONE
WHILE I WAS IN CHARGE.
SEE? NOT SO HARD,
WHAT YOU DO.
- YOU JUST GOT LUCKY THIS ONCE.
YOU REALLY THINK
I COULD LEAVE HERE
AND EVERYTHING WOULD BE FINE?
- I THINK EVERYTHING
WOULD BE FINE BUT YOU.
I DON'T THINK
YOU CAN LEAVE.
- WELL, LINDSAY,
IF I DIDN'T HAVE THAT PHONE CALL
FROM THE ZONING COMMITTEE--
- YOU'D HAVE NO REASON TO LIVE.
I'LL HAVE IT FORWARDED
TO YOUR CELL.
- GREAT. I'LL LEAVE.
NOT A PROBLEM.
I, UH, CAN SPEND
SOME TIME WITH MY SON.
SO YOU'RE IN CHARGE.
TRY NOT TO BRING
THE WHOLE COMPANY DOWN.
- LIKE THAT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
narrator: SO THE EMPLOYEES
HEADED OFF TO CATALINA,
PROVIDING
THE SURVEILLANCE TEAM
THAT HAD INSTALLED
THE LIGHTING
WITH THE OPPORTUNITY
THEY NEEDED.
- THE PLACE IS EMPTY.
- ALL RIGHT. LET'S GET IN THERE
AND BRING THIS COMPANY DOWN.
narrator: AT PRISON,
GEORGE SR. WAS MAKING CONVERTS
TO HIS NEW WAY OF LIFE.
- YOU WON'T REGRET THIS,
LITTLE JUSTICE.
- UH, OKAY, WHAT SAY FROM NOW ON
WE CALL YOU DAVID BEN-AVRAM?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
TO MY GUY HERE?
- NOTHING. I'M JUST MERELY
PROVIDING HIM WITH OPTIONS.
[kisses]
THIS YARMULKE WILL PROTECT YOU,
DAVID BEN-AVRAM.
- PIPE!
- I'VE GOT WORSE PLANNED FOR YOU
IF YOU KEEP TRYING TO
CONVERT MY TEAM.
- OKAY, HOLD IT.
HOLD IT, NOW.
WAIT, NOW,
I'M DOING NO SUCH THING.
AND BOTH OF OUR RELIGIONS
HAVE A LOT TO OFFER.
THERE'S THE JEWISH NOTION
OF HEAVEN AND THAT--
THAT IT CAN BE ATTAINED
HERE ON EARTH,
AND THERE IS YOUR BELIEF IN
THE CLEANSING POWER OF THE PIPE.
[breathes deeply]
- NO MORE TEACHING FROM YOU.
- NO TEACHING.
NO TEACHING.
narrator: IT WAS AT THAT MOMENT
THAT GEORGE SR.
REUNITED WITH HIS SON-IN-LAW.
- FATHER.
- TOBIAS, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M HERE TO STUDY WITH YOU,
TO LEARN FROM YOU.
TEACH ME.
- THERE'S NO TEACHING.
THERE'S NO TEACHING.
- WHO IS THIS LITTLE [bleep]?
- WILL, IT'S BEEN QUITE A WHILE
SINCE ANYBODY CALLED ME A TYKE,
BUT, NO,
I AM DR. TOBIAS FUNKE.
OR, WITH YOUR HELP,
FRIGHTENED INMATE \#2.
[chuckles]
AND WHO IS THIS
SHINY BUILDING OF A MAN?
- OH, I'M VERY SCARED RIGHT NOW.
- OH, WE'RE STARTING.
OH, YES. LET ME GET SOMETHING
TO WRITE WITH.
narrator:
BACK AT THE BANANA STAND,
ANNYONG HAD ARRIVED.
- GUYS, IT LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO
RESTOCK ON NUTS TONIGHT,
ALL RIGHT?
NOW, LISTEN,
I KNOW THAT THAT'S
NOBODY'S FAVORITE
SATURDAY NIGHT,
BUT I THINK IF WE JUST
POWER THROUGH
AND KEEP OUR HEADS DOWN,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO--
- ANNYONG AND I ARE FINE HERE.
I MEAN, YOU DON'T HAVE TO--
- ANNYONG.
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO
WORRY SO MUCH.
I MEAN, OBVIOUSLY,
YOUR DAD DOESN'T
WANT TO SPEND TIME WITH YOU,
BUT, YOU KNOW,
GO TO THE BEACH OR WHATEVER.
YOU KNOW,
HE'S JUST NOT AROUND, OKAY?
- HE NO HAVE FATHER?
OLDER LADY ADOPT HIM TOO?
- NO, HE HAVE FATHER.
FATHER NO LOVE HIM.
- NO, HE LOVE ME--LOVES ME.
HE LOVES ME.
SO, ALL RIGHT.
MAYBE I WILL TAKE
A LITTLE TIME OFF
AND GO TO THE BEACH
OR SOMETHING.
- I WENT TO BEACH ONCE.
NEXT THING I KNOW,
I'M IN CRATE NEXT TO PIG.
- [singing] YEE-HAW,
GET ALONG
narrator: INSTEAD,
GEORGE MICHAEL
HAD DECIDED TO LEAVE
FOR HIS FATHER'S OFFICE
AND HAVE LUNCH WITH HIM.
MEANWHILE, THE WHITE COLLAR
BLUTH COMPANY EMPLOYEES
HAD MADE IT THROUGH THE
FIRST LEG OF THEIR JOURNEY
AND WERE ABOUT TO
EMBARK ON THE SECOND.
AND LUCILLE,
TAKING MICHAEL'S ADVICE,
RETURNED HOME FROM QUANTITY PLUS
WITH A PROBLEM.
- LUPE! BUSTER?
ANNYONG? HELLO?
narrator: WITH LUPE GONE
AND THE REST OF HER FAMILY
WORKING FOR ONCE, LUCILLE
REALIZED SHE MISSED THEM.
- WELL, NOW, WHO THE HELL
IS GONNA UNLOAD THE CAR?
HOLA. IS ROSA STILL ALIVE?
NO? HMM.
OKAY. THIS IS NOT MY DAY.
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
STOPPED BY TO SAY HELLO
TO HIS SON AND FOUND OUT
HE HAD GONE TO THE BEACH.
SO MICHAEL WENT
TO FIND GEORGE MICHAEL
AND ALSO TRY TO
FIGURE OUT A SOLUTION
FOR HIS SPACE PROBLEM.
- [woman singing] AND I WONDER
HOW LONG I'LL LAST
narrator: AND THEN
HE DECIDED THAT PERHAPS HE, TOO,
SHOULD TRY A LITTLE RELAXATION.
BACK AT THE CONSTRUCTION SITE,
GOB WAS ALSO READY
TO TAKE THE AFTERNOON OFF.
- SCREW THIS!
I HAVE MY PRIDE.
I DON'T CARE
HOW MUCH THEY'RE PAYING ME.
- YOU GOT PAID?
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL
MAKING SACRIFICES.
- YEAH, WELL, MAYBE IT'S TIME
FOR SOME OF THOSE BIG SHOTS
AT THE BLUTH COMPANY
TO START MAKING SOME SACRIFICES.
I SAY WE
SHUT DOWN CONSTRUCTION!
- HEY, HEY, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHY ARE WE STOPPING?
THIS IS FUN!
WE SHOULD DO THIS
JUST FOR THE FUN.
- EASY FOR HIM TO SAY.
HE GOT HIS PAYCHECK TOO.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
- THAT'S NOT RIGHT.
- COME ON, YOU DOUCHE BAGS.
WE'RE ALL ON THE SAME TEAM!
- DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
HE'LL NEVER STAND UP TO THE MAN.
- HE'S A CHICKEN,
A CHICKEN.
[staccato cawing]
- MY WHOLE LIFE
YOU'VE CALLED ME A CHICKEN,
BUT THAT'S OVER NOW.
I HAVE NOTHING TO PROVE.
[staccato cawing and clapping]
- THAT IS NOT HOW
A CHICKEN SOUNDS.
CHICKENS DON'T CLAP!
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
LISTEN, THIS IS NOT
HOW WE SETTLE THINGS ON A SITE.
WE GOT OUR OWN WAY
OF FINDING OUT WHO'S A CHICKEN
BY A LITTLE GAME
WE LIKE TO CALL "CHICKEN."
- I HOPE YOU'RE UP TO THIS,
BUSTER.
THIS IS A GAME OF COURAGE,
A GAME FOR MEN.
- YEAH, WELL,
IT'S A GAME I'M READY FOR!
- UH-OH.
MY SEAT DOESN'T HAVE A CUSHION.
- READY? GO!
OH, YEAH, I'M DEFINITELY
GONNA NEED A CUSHION.
narrator: AS THE BLUTHS
SQUARED OFF,
LINDSAY DEALT WITH
THE NEWS OF THE WORK STOPPAGE.
[elevator bell dings]
- THIS WASN'T MY FAULT.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE MICHAEL.
- SO WAIT.
MY DAD'S NOT HERE?
- NOPE. HE WENT OUT FOR LUNCH
TO HAVE FUN.
BUT EVERYTHING'S FINE.
I MEAN, IF HE ASKS,
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
MY STYLE WORKS.
THIS PLACE IS HUMMING ALONG.
thump!
- SO WAIT.
MY DAD SAID THAT
HE WAS WAITING FOR A CALL,
THAT HE HAD TO STAY HERE.
- OH, NO,
HE CAN GET THAT CALL ANYWHERE.
I JUST HAVE TO
FORWARD IT TO HIM.
- HUH.
- HEY, WOULD YOU MIND RUNNING
THINGS FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
- I'M--I'M NOT REALLY--
- IT'S NOT HARD.
narrator: AND SO LINDSAY
HEADED OFF TO DEAL
WITH THE WORK STOPPAGE
PROBLEM AT THE SITE.
[telephone ringing]
LINDSAY KNEW MICHAEL
WOULD BE FURIOUS
IF HE FOUND OUT
THE BUILDING HAD STOPPED,
SO SHE HAD TO FIND
A WAY TO START IT,
AND THAT'S
WHEN SHE SAW LUPE'S FAMILY.
- HEY, WHO'S READY
TO HAVE SOME FUN?
- UH...
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL CONTINUED
HIS RELAXATION AT THE BEACH.
- OKAY, THESE UNITS
AREN'T TOO CLOSE TOGETHER.
WE CAN GET AWAY WITH THIS,
RIGHT, PEOPLE?
ALL RIGHT.
JUST SPEED IT UP.
COME ON. KEEP YOUR HEADS DOWN.
POWER THROUGH.
[phone ringing]
OH, NO. WHERE IS--
WHERE'S MY PHONE?
- I USED IT
TO DIG THE "B" UNIT.
- YOU WHAT?
- I'LL GET IT.
- NO, NO.
YOU'RE GONNA RUIN IT!
WHAT AM I DOING?
[ringing continues]
HELLO.
- HI, DAD.
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL,
WHERE ARE YOU?
I'M AT THE OFFICE.
LINDSAY PUT ME IN CHARGE HERE
'CAUSE THERE WAS NOBODY HERE,
AND SHE HAD TO GO
TO THE CONSTRUCTION SITE,
'CAUSE THE WORKERS
STOPPED WORKING.
- OH, GREAT.
NOW WE'RE NEVER GONNA
FINISH PHASE THREE, AND
EVERYTHING'S GONNA FALL APART.
THIS WHOLE THING
IS GONNA CAVE IN,
AND WE'RE GONNA
BE LEFT WITH A BUNCH OF--
GREAT.
NOW MY SAND CASTLE
HAS A GIANT POOL IN IT.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL SAW THE SOLUTION
TO HIS SPACE PROBLEM.
- I GOTTA GO, BUDDY.
- HE'S MAKING A SAND CASTLE?
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
NOTICED SOMETHING TOO.
HE KNEW HIS FATHER
HAD ALWAYS LOVED HIM,
BUT AT THIS MOMENT,
HE WAS ACTUALLY
HOLDING THE PROOF IN HIS HANDS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
IT WAS AT THIS MOMENT
THAT THE INVESTIGATORS
WENT INTO ACTION.
- THERE'S THE KID.
- COVER'S BLOWN.
GET OUT.
- I'VE GOT
A CLEAN SHOT OVER HERE.
- NO, NO,
GET THE PROOF.
HE'S GOT THE EVIDENCE FILE.
- COME ON. COME ON.
I TOLD YOU
TO FIND A STUD. GO!
narrator: AND BACK
AT THE CONSTRUCTION SITE,
BUSTER AND GOB'S SHOWDOWN
WAS REACHING
A DRAMATIC CONCLUSION.
- [whimpering]
ding!
- WOW.
WHO WON?
narrator:
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME,
GOB SAW HIS BROTHER AS A MAN.
- LET'S GET BACK TO WORK, GUYS.
narrator: AND LINDSAY ARRIVED,
SUDDENLY TRYING
A NEW MANAGEMENT STYLE.
- WHAT'S THIS NOW?
- OKAY.
SO YOU GUYS
DON'T WANNA WORK? FINE.
I'VE GOT A STAIR CAR
FULL OF MEXICAN LABORERS
THAT WOULD LOVE A DAY'S WORK.
- "LABORERS"?
I'M A PROFESSOR
OF AMERICAN STUDIES
AT THE UNIVERSITY
OF MEXICO CITY.
- I TOOK A DANCE CLASS THERE.
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE TAKING US
TO CATALINA.
WHAT HAPPENED TO CATALINA?
- [singing] YEE-HAW
- YOU'D BRING IN SCABS,
JUST LIKE THAT?
- WATCH ME.
GO TO WORK!
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WE'RE SHUTTING IT DOWN.
- MICHAEL, I'VE SOLVED THIS.
- NO, NO, IT'S NOT YOU.
IT'S ME. IT'S WRONG.
THE PLAN IS WRONG.
WE GOTTA GET RID OF
THE INDIVIDUAL SWIMMING POOLS
AND PUT IN A GREAT BIG
COMMUNAL ONE
RIGHT IN THE CENTER.
AND, LINDSAY, YOU WERE RIGHT.
WE'VE ALL BEEN WORKING
A LITTLE BIT TOO HARD.
YOU CAN'T MANAGE BY THREATENING
AND PUSHING PEOPLE,
AND SOMETIMES YOU HAVE TO
REWARD HARD WORK.
MAYBE REWARD IT WITH A PARTY.
[cheering]
RIGHT.
I DIDN'T MEAN TONIGHT,
JUST SOME TIME IN THE FUTURE
WHEN WE HAVE
SOME EXTRA FOOD AND LIQUOR.
- LUPE!
LUPE, I NEED HELP
WITH THE GROCERIES!
- HOW ABOUT JUST LIQUOR?
narrator: AND THE TWO BLUTH MEN
FINALLY DID RELAX.
- THANKS FOR COMING OUT, BUDDY.
I'VE BEEN DYING
TO GET SOME TIME WITH YOU,
I REALLY HAVE.
- THAT'S OKAY.
I KNOW HOW MUCH
YOU CARE ABOUT ME.
UNFORTUNATELY,
SO DOES THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
WANT MORE PUNCH?
- SURE.
WAIT. THE FEDS?
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
TOBIAS GETS AN INSIGHT
INTO FEAR.
- WELL, LET'S DISCUSS
THIS BUNKING SITUATION.
- YOU'LL BE SLEEPING
UNDER ME FOR A WHILE.
- I SOLD YOU
FOR A PACK OF CIGARETTES.
narrator: AND THE EMPLOYEES
FIND A NEW DIRECTION.
- WHOA! WHOA!
WHAT ARE YOU FOLKS DOIN'
ON THIS PART OF THE MOUNTAIN?
- WE'RE LOST.
- WELL, I CAN GIVE YOU
A RIDE BACK INTO TOWN.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
BUCK, BANJO,
GET ON UP HERE. COME ON, BOY.
[yipping]
THERE YOU GO.
- [singing]
GET ALONG