[narrator]
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
[narrator]
MICHAEL BLUTH AND HIS FAMILY HAD
GATHERED AT THE COURTHOUSE...
TO DISCUSS GEORGE SR.'S
UPCOMING TRIAL.
- DO NOT ASK ME HOW I DID IT--
THEY OFFERED US A PLEA BARGAIN.
- REALLY? THERE'S A CHANCE
WE DON'T HAVE TO GO TO TRIAL?
- ABSOLUTELY,
AND I SAY WE TAKE IT,
BECAUSE WE WILL NEVER GET
AN OFFER THIS GOOD AGAIN.
- WOW.
- GREAT. WHAT'S THE OFFER?
- WELL, I DIDN'T READ IT.
I JUST GOT IT YESTERDAY.
F.Y.I.,
I'M TRYING TO GET BACK
INTO THE DATING WORLD.
HEY, YOU'RE NOT ONE OF THOSE
SILLY MEN THAT'S DRESSED LIKE
A WOMAN, ARE YOU?
- NO, BABY.
I'M THE REAL THING.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW
A PERSON CAN PUT THEIR SEX LIFE
IN FRONT OF THEIR WORK.
- HE'S A MAN, MICHAEL.
HE NEEDS A WOMAN.
- CAN WE GET BACK TO WORK,
FOLKS?
WE'VE ONLY GOT 24 HOURS
TO RESPOND,
AND NO MATTER WHAT THIS IS,
IT IS BETTER THAN GOING
TO TRIAL.
- YOUR FATHER'S NOT HERE.
I'LL SPEAK FOR HIM.
HE LOVES IT.
HE'S CRAZY ABOUT THE PLEA.
HE'S DYING TO
GET OUT OF THAT PRISON
AND BE WITH A WOMAN AGAIN.
[narrator]
IN FACT, GEORGE SR.
HAD A WOMAN IN HIS LIFE--
CINDI LIGHTBALLOON,
A FAN OF HIS CAGED WISDOM
VIDEO SERIES,
WITH WHOM HE'D HAD
FLEETING PHYSICAL CONTACT.
THAT MORNING HOWEVER,
SHE HAD SOME STARTLING NEWS
FOR HIM.
- I'M A MOLE.
- WELL, YOU KNOW, GOD DOESN'T
CARE HOW BIG YOUR TEETH ARE.
YES, YOU COULD GO TO A DENTIST.
YOU COULD-- WHOO.
YOU COULD GRIND OFF ABOUT--
I DON'T KNOW-- 30%, MAYBE MORE.
YEAH, I WOULDN'T MISS IT.
- NO, NO, NO. I MEAN,
I'M AN UNDERCOVER
GOVERNMENT AGENT.
I WAS SENT HERE
TO INVESTIGATE YOU.
UP UNTIL LAST WEEK,
MY BEING IN LOVE WITH YOU
WAS JUST AN ACT.
- HMM.
- BUT NOW I WANT TO
BE WITH YOU.
AND I KNOW
YOU CAN BEAT THIS CASE
THEY HAVE AGAINST YOU.
I KNOW THIS FOR A FACT.
- I WANT TO FIGHT THIS THING.
I CAN BEAT IT.
I KNOW IT FOR A FACT.
- WE'RE TAKING THE PLEA.
- LUCILLE,
WE'RE NOT TAKING A PLEA.
- WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT THE PLEA IS YET.
- IS THAT A SHOT AT ME?
'CAUSE THAT MAKES ME
WANT TO READ IT ALL THE LESS.
- YOU HAVE ANOTHER ONE OF THESE?
- YES, I DO.
- WE'LL BOTH READ IT.
- YOU'RE GOING TO READ THAT?
- YEAH.
- IT'S PRETTY THICK.
- HE THINKS HE'S A LAWYER
'CAUSE HE PLAYED ONE
IN 10th GRADE.
[narrator]
IN ORDER TO SATISFY
AN ENGLISH REQUIREMENT,
MICHAEL APPEARED IN
THE DRAMA CLUB'S PRODUCTION...
OF AN ORIGINAL PLAY,
THE TRIAL OF CAPTAIN HOOK.
- [singing]
YOU'RE A CROOK, CAPTAIN HOOK
JUDGE, WON'T YOU THROW
THE BOOK AT THE PIRATE--
- I DON'T REMEMBER THAT.
- WELL, YOU LEFT DURING MY SOLO.
AND I'M SURPRISED MY TWIN SISTER
CAN REMEMBER THAT,
CONSIDERING SHE WAS REPEATING
THE NINTH GRADE AT THE TIME.
- I DON'T REMEMBER THAT.
- BIG SURPRISE, MOM.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU
EVER TOOK AN INTEREST
IN OUR LIVES.
HONESTLY, IF I EVER DID
TO MAEBY WHAT YOU-
[narrator]
LINDSAY RECALLED
THAT EARLIER THAT DAY...
SHE HAD RECEIVED A LETTER
FROM THE HIGH SCHOOL
ABOUT HER OWN DAUGHTER.
AND SO LATER,
LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
TRIED A MORE HANDS-ON APPROACH
TO PARENTING.
- WE WOULD LIKE YOU TO TUTOR
OUR DAUGHTER.
- NOW, OF COURSE,
WE'RE HAVING A BIT
OF A CASH-FLOW PROBLEM,
BUT I ASSURE YOU,
IF YOU BRING OUR
LITTLE GIRL'S GRADES UP,
I WILL PACK
YOUR SWEET PINK MOUTH
WITH SO MUCH ICE CREAM,
YOU'LL BE THE ENVY
OF EVERY JERRY AND JANE
ON THE BLOCK.
- WE'RE THE ONLY HOUSE
- PERHAPS WE SHOULD
GET SOMEBODY ELSE.
[narrator]
MICHAEL, MEANWHILE, HAD GONE
TO THE BAR ACROSS THE STREET
FROM THE COURTHOUSE...
TO READ THE PLEA OFFER.
- "NOT TO EXCEED FIVE YEARS,
BUT NO LESS THAN THREE."
- SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I'M SO MAD AT BARRY
I CAN'T EVEN FOCUS.
THAT GUY'S OUT DATING?
I MEAN, I'D LOVE TO BE DATING,
BUT I--
- CAN'T RELAX?
- NO. I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR A RELATIONSHIP.
THIS IS IMPORTANT.
- NO ONE SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT A RELATIONSHIP, MICHAEL.
IF YOU'D SLEPT WITH MORE THAN
FOUR WOMEN, YOU'D KNOW THAT.
- I HAVE, GOB.
- MORE THAN FIVE?
LET'S SAY "FIVE".
THIS IS A COURTHOUSE BAR,
MICHAEL.
THESE ARE PROFESSIONAL,
AGGRESSIVE WOMEN...
WHO ARE LOOKING FOR NOTHING MORE
THAN A ONE-NIGHT STAND.
NO REAL NAMES,
NO PROMISES.
- I'M NOT A ONE-NIGHT STAND
KIND OF GUY.
I DON'T LIKE
LYING TO WOMEN.
- THESE ARE LAWYERS--
THAT'S LATIN FOR "LIAR."
- I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M STILL
READING THE SAME SENTENCE.
HOW CAN SOMETHING BE
"NO LESS THAN THREE"
IF IT EXCEEDS SIX?
I MEAN, SIX IS STILL
MORE THAN THREE, RIGHT?
- YEAH, AND IT'S STILL
MORE THAN FIVE.
- OH! OH. OH, I'M SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
I'M FALLING ALL OVER YOU.
[chuckles]
- LET ME MOVE DOWN.
I'M JUST WORKING
ON THIS PLEA.
- IF YOU'RE PLEADING WITH ME
TO HAVE A DRINK WITH YOU,
YOU CAN STOP BEGGING.
- [chuckles]
NO, NO. IT'S A--
IT'S A PLEA
FOR THIS CASE THAT I'M--
I'M SORRY--- YOU WANT A DRINK.
- WELL, I DIDN'T COME HERE
FOR THE VIEW.
I'LL HAVE
A VODKA MARTINI.
- I'LL TELL HIM.
- SO, ANOTHER LAWYER, HUH?
- VODKA MARTINI!
- I'M MAGGIE LIZER,
AS IN "MAGGIE LIES HER ASS OFF."
[laughing]
ONE PERSON LAUGHED AT THAT ONCE,
AND I DON'T KNOW
WHY I KEEP TRYING IT.
- NO, IT'S GOOD. YEAH.
- WHAT KIND OF LAW
DO YOU PRACTICE?
- [young Michael singing]
YOU'RE A CROOK, CAPTAIN HOOK
- MARITIME. MARITIME LAW.
LAWYERS OF THE SEA.
- OH.
SUBMARINE CHASER.
[giggles]
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
- CHARETH.
OH. SO THEN
WHAT'S YOUR LAST NAME?
- CUTE STORY--
- CUTESTORY?
- YES.
CHARETH CUTESTORY.
- THAT'S
AN INTERESTING NAME.
- IS IT?
- SO HERE'S THE TEST
THAT I FAILED.
- OH, OKAY. YEAH, I SEE
THE PROBLEM RIGHT AWAY.
YOU, UH-- YOU GOT
ALL THE ANSWERS WRONG.
YOU KNOW YOU, YOU EVEN
GOT YOUR NAME WRONG HERE.
IT SAYS, "S. FUNKE.
- YEAH, WELL, SEE,
WHAT THEY WANT YOU TO DO...
IS PUT AN "S" IF YOU'RE SINGLE,
AN "M" IF YOU'RE MARRIED.
I MEAN, MOST OF US
ARE ALL SINGLE, BUT IT'S
A WHOLE GOVERNMENT THING, SO--
- YEAH. OKAY. THE FIRST THING
YOU WANT TO DO WHEN YOU'RE
DEALING WITH FRACTIONS--
- YEAH.
SO I'M GONNA GO, OKAY?
SO JUST FILL IN
ALL THE RIGHT ANSWERS HERE,
AND I'LL SEE WHERE I WENT WRONG.
AND YOU'RE GETTING
PAID FOR THIS RIGHT?
- THERE WAS TALK OF ICE CREAM,
BUT NOT EXACTLY ON MY TERMS.
WOW! WHERE DID YOU GET ALL THAT?
DO YOU HAVE A JOB OR SOMETHING?
- NO, BUT YOU DO.
NOW, LOOK.
DON'T FEEL GUILTY.
I DON'T REALLY NEED TUTORING
ANYWAYS, OKAY?
ENJOY THE 200 BUCKS.
- OH, THERE--
THERE'S SIX 20s HERE.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- RIGHT.
[narrator]
AFTER AN EVENING OF DRINKING,
MICHAEL, BEING THE SENSIBLE ONE,
OFFERED TO GIVE MAGGIE
A RIDE HOME.
- OH-HO!
[giggling]
[narrator]
THE NEXT MORNING,
MICHAEL WAS WONDERING...
HOW TO END
HIS FIRST ONE-NIGHT STAND.
- COFFEE?
- HI. YES, PLEASE.
THANK YOU. THAT'S GREAT.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
I AM GOING TO HAVE TO
READ THAT PLEA SOON, OKAY?
'CAUSE IT'S A BIG CASE.
BUT I PROMISE LATER
I WILL CALL--
[narrator]
MICHAEL STRUGGLED
TO FOLLOW GOB'S INSTRUCTION
TO JUST WALK AWAY.
- I'LL-- I'LL-- I'LL CALL, OKAY?
ALL RIGHT?
HEY. WHO'S THIS?
- OH, THAT'S JUSTICE.
- HI, JUSTICE.
IS HE AS HANDSOME AS HE SMELLS?
- I DIDN'T-- I DIDN'T KNOW
THAT YOU HAD A DOG.
- HOW ELSE
AM I GONNA GET TO WORK?
- YOU RIDE A DOG TO WORK?
- [chuckles]
YOU ARE FUNNY.
LET ME SEE THAT SMILE.
- WELL, IT'S TOUGH
WITH YOUR HANDS IN THE WAY.
- [laughing]
SAY WHEN.
- OKAY.
[narrator]
AND SUDDENLY, MICHAEL
RECALLED SOME NON SEQUITURS
FROM THE NIGHT BEFORE.
- SO, TELL ME SOMETHING PERSONAL
ABOUT YOURSELF.
- UH, WELL, I HAVE
AN IRREVERSIBLE CASE
OF OCULAR RETINOBLASTOMA.
- HEY. I THOUGHT WE SAID
NO MORE LAW TALK.
I REALLY CAN'T SEE
ANYBODY RIGHT NOW.
- OH, WELL,
I CAN'T SEE ANYBODY EVER.
I'M BLIND.
- I'M WASTED.
[narrator]
MICHAEL REALIZED
THAT THE WOMAN HE WAS ATTEMPTG
TO NEVER SEE AGAIN WAS BLIND,
AND HE WAS OVERCOME WITH GUILT.
- WHEN... CAN WE GO OUT AGAIN?
- REALLY?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE, LIKE,
JUST INTO THIS ONE-NIGHT STAND
KIND OF THING.
COME ON.
I TOOK A BLIND WOMAN HOME
WITH NO INTENTION
OF DATING HER AGAIN?
PLEASE!
- [guffaws]
[narrator]
GEORGE SR. WAS CONTINUING
TO EXPLOIT HIS RELATIONSHIP
WITH CINDI.
- WHAT-- WHAT EVIDENCE
DOES THE GOVERNMENT HAVE...
ON OLD WISE GEORGE,
BY THE WAY?
- OH, I HATE IT
WHEN YOU CALL YOURSELF OLD!
- [laughs]
- YOU'RE NEW TO ME!
- OH, THAT'S-- THAT'S NICE.
DO THEY HAVE A-- A FILE
OR TAPES?
- OH, WHAT'S THE USE?
YOU'RE MARRIED.
- YEAH. LET ME ASK YOU--
- WE'LL NEVER BE TOGETHER.
- LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
- LET'S JUST GO BACK
TO WHAT WE DO BEST.
- OKAY.
- TWEAK ME.
- GEORGE!
- LUCILLE!
HI. UH, THIS IS NOT
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE.
- IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE TWEAKING HER NIPPLES
THROUGH A CHAIN-LINK FENCE.
- YEP. YEAH, THAT'S IT.
- IS THIS WHY YOU WANTED TO
FIGHT THIS THING?
SO YOU COULD RUN OFF
WITH THIS GREAT REDWOOD
OF A WHORE?
- LISTEN TO ME.
SHE IS A FAN OF MINE.
SHE HAS SEEN EVERYTHING
I'VE DONE.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
EVERYTHING.
- WELL, SO HAVE I,
AND I'M NOT GOING TO
PUT UP WITH IT ANYMORE.
- OKAY.
- YOU'LL BE HEARING
FROM BARRY.
- ALL RIGHT. HON?
HONEY? HON?
- OH, GOD.
I'M A HOME-WRECKER.
- OH, NO.
- I NEVER WANTED
TO BE THAT PERSON.
- NO, NO.
NO. NO, CINDI, IT'S--
CINDI?
[narrator]
MICHAEL CAME HOME UPSET THAT
HIS ONE-NIGHT STAND WASN'T OVER.
- YOU SHOULD HAVE
STAYED WITH ME LAST NIGHT.
YOU COULD HAVE SEEN ME
GET SOME MAJOR ACTION
FROM A MAJOR BLONDE...
WHO JUST MAJORED
IN MARINE BIOLOGY,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
WHAT THAT MEANS.
I ACTUALLY HAD A PRETTY
INTERESTING NIGHT MYSELF.
- REALLY?
WHAT'D YOU DO, READ THE PLEA?
- NO, I DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE TO.
I WENT HOME WITH SOMEONE.
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH HER?
- NOTHING'S WRONG WITH HER.
SHE'S BLIND.
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
- I DIDN'T KNOW AT THE TIME.
AND NOW I'VE GOT TO TAKE HER
AND HER DOG TO THE PARK.
- YOU'VE GOT WORK TO DO.
YOU'VE GOT TO READ THAT PLEA.
- I KNOW.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS TRYING
TO DO LAST NIGHT
WHEN YOU PUT ME UP TO ALL THIS.
- NO, I DIDN'T.
- YES, YOU DID.
- I TOLD YOU TO WALK AWAY.
I TOLD YOU
TO GIVE A FAKE NAME.
- I DID.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
I'M CHARETH CUTESTORY,
A PIRATE LAWYER.
IT WAS AIRTIGHT.
- BOY, YOU HAD TO WORK HARD
TO BAG THIS BLIND GIRL, HUH?
- I CERTAINLY CAN'T
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF HER NOW,
KNOWING WHAT I KNOW.
- WHAT? NO.
MICHAEL, YOU CAN!
DON'T YOU--
YOU'VE JUST WON THE GOLD MEDAL
AT THE SEXUAL SPECIAL OLYMPICS!
SHE CAN'T EVER FIND YOU AGAIN.
DON'T YOU SEE
THAT YOU'RE SO LUCKY?
GOD! HOW DO YOU NOT S--
- WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
DIDN'T YOU "BAG" SOME WOMAN
YOU'RE NEVER GOING TO SEE AGAIN?
- WELL, I SCREWED UP.
I BROKE A COUPLE
OF MY OWN RULES LAST NIGHT.
SHE KNOWS
THAT I'M GOB BLUTH...
AND WE GOT MARRIED
AND I JUST--
- WHAT?
- WELL, SHE WAS A DARER.
SHE'S ONE OF THOSE GIRLS
WHO JUST DARES YOU
TO DO THINGS.
- YOU MARRIED HER?
- I NEEDED A DARE!
[narrator]
WHAT HAD STARTED
AS AN INNOCENT FLIRTATION...
HAD TURNED INTO A SERIES
OF ESCALATING CHALLENGES.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE EVENING WAS DRAINING...
AND THE ONE THING THEY NEVER
DARED EACH OTHER TO DO
WAS CONSUMMATE THE MARRIAGE.
- WELL, GUESS IT'S TIME
TO SEAL THE DEAL.
- OH, WAIT! WHAT TIME IS IT?
OH, GOD! "SEAL THE DEAL."
MY SEAL DEAL!
I GOTTA GET TO SEA LAND.
I'M SELLING
FIVE OF THEIR SICKEST SEALS
TO A THIRD-WORLD ZOO.
- DID YOU SAY SEALS?
- YES! I TOLD YOU FOUR HOURS
AGO, I SELL SEALS!
GOD! DO YOU EVER
LISTEN TO WHAT I SAY?
- I'M SORRY
I DON'T MEMORIZE EVERY WORD
THAT COMES OUT OF YOUR MOUTH.
SOMETIMES
I JUST LIKE TO THINK--
THINK MY THOUGHTS.
- WE'LL TALK ABOUT THIS
WHEN I GET HOME.
- IT WAS HOT.
- BOY, THE LENGTHS YOU'LL GO
TO SLEEP WITH A WOMAN.
- BELIEVE ME,
WE DIDN'T DO ANY SLEEPING.
I HAD SEX LAST NIGHT.
[narrator]
BUT HE REALLY DIDN'T.
- YES, I DID.
[narrator]
AND LATER,
MICHAEL ARRIVED FOR HIS DATE.
- HEY!
- I'M SO SORRY
THAT I'M LATE.
- I THOUGHT
I SMELLED YOU COMING.
- MM. YEAH, HERE I AM.
- I THOUGHT SO.
DID YOU SMELL HIM?
DID YOU SMELL THE HANDSOME MAN,
JUSTICE?
- "HANDSOME."
YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY EVIDENCE OF HANDSOME.
- WELL, THAT'S TRUE.
BUT I CAN FEEL HANDSOME.
- MMM.
- THAT FEELS HANDSOMEY.
[chuckles]
SO YOU DIDN'T GET A CASE OF
"I JUST HAD A ONE-NIGHT STAND
WITH A BLIND GIRL"-ITUS?
- NO, OF COURSE NOT.
ONE-NIGHT STAND? PLEASE!
THIS IS
OUR SECOND DATE NOW.
AND I WANNA SEE--
AND I WANNA SEE YOU AGAIN
TONIGHT, SO, UM,
IF IT'S A ONE-NIGHT STAND,
I'M NOT VERY GOOD AT IT.
- BUT NOW, LISTEN,
AREN'T YOU BUSY
WITH THE TRIAL?
- UM, YES, OF COURSE.
I'M VERY, VERY BUSY.
BUT NOT TOO BUSY FOR YOU.
NOT TOO BUSY
FOR A LITTLE WALK
RIGHT NOW MAYBE.
I'LL BE YOUR SEEING EYE DOG.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
OKAY?
- OH. SHOULD WE LEAVE
JUSTICE HERE?
- UM, YES. HE'LL BE FINE,
WON'T YOU, BOY? HUH?
- JUSTICE, STAY! STAY!
DESCRIBE THIS
TO ME, CHARETH.
DESCRIBE TO ME
HOW BEAUTIFUL THE PARK IS.
- OH, I WISH YOU COULD SEE IT.
IT'S JUST BEAUTIFUL.
THERE'S AN ELDERLY COUPLE
WALKING HAND IN HAND.
THEY'RE HAVING
A WONDERFUL TIME.
- YEAH?
- "ALREADY SERVED,
NOT TO EXCEED SIX YEARS
BUT NO LESS THAN THREE--"
UH, THREE YEARS
IS WHAT I GIVE THEM...
AND THEN ONE OF THEM DIES
AND THE OTHER ONE
IS NOT TOO FAR BEHIND.
- I CAN SMELL
RIGHT THROUGH YOU, CHARETH.
YOU'RE READING.
- LEASH YOUR DOG,
YOU-- [beep]
- UH, YES.
- [chuckles]
YEAH.
[narrator]
AND GEORGE SR.
WAS WORKING ON A ROADSIDE
BEAUTIFICATION EFFORT...
BROKERED
BY WARDEN STEFAN GENTLES.
- INMATE BLUTH.
- YES, SIR?
- I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT LAST NIGHT...
I WATCHED
A VERY IMPRESSIVE VIDEOTAPE
OF THE TITLE CAGED WISDOM.
I WAS STRUCK BY THE DUAL LIFE
OF THE SPIRITUAL MAN.
AND I DID VERY MUCH ENJOY
THE BLOOPER BONUS FOOTAGE
AT THE END.
[laughs]
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
I ALMOST DID STRANGLE MYSELF
ON MY OWN PRAYER SHAWL.
- A SELF-CHOKING
FOR THE AGES.
THERE'S A SHASTA CAN THERE
YOU SEEMED TO HAVE MISSED.
- OKAY.
[narrator]
MOMENTS LATER, CINDI ARRIVED.
- THANK YOU, WARDEN.
- GEORGE!
I HAD TO SEE YOU.
I'M SORRY I LEFT BEFORE.
I JUST FELT SO AWFUL.
BUT I KEPT
THINKING ABOUT US.
- YES.
- ABOUT OUR FUTURE.
YES, I--
- AND I KNOW FOR A FACT
WE CAN HAVE ONE.
- OKAY. WHAT EVIDENCE
DO THEY HAVE ON ME?
YOU KEEP TALKING ABOUT A FACT?
YOU KEEP SAYING,
"I KNOW FOR A FACT."
WHAT FACT?
- FAITH.
I HAVE FAITH
MY PRAYERS WILL FREE YOU.
- FAITH IS NOT A FACT!
- OH, YES, IT IS.
YOU SAID SO YOURSELF
IN CAGED WISDOM.
[narrator]
GEORGE SR. HAD SAID
"FAITH IS A FACT."
UNFORTUNATELY,
IT WAS IN THE CAGED WISDOM
BLOOPER BONUS FOOTAGE.
- FAITH IS A FACT.
NO. FAITH IS A FACET.
I ALMOST SAID FAITH IS A FACT.
[wheezy laugh]
I AM GOING TO TRIAL
BECAUSE YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT A BLOOPER REEL IS?
GUARD!
[narrator]
BACK AT THE HIGH SCHOOL,
GEORGE MICHAEL RAN INTO MAEBY.
- I GOT AN "A."
CHECK IT OUT.
GREAT JOB.
TAKE SOME MORE MONEY.
LOOK.
I GOTTA GO.
I'M GOING TO THIS FUND-RAISER
FOR A SICK GIRL, OKAY?
[narrator]
THIS RANG FALSE
TO GEORGE MICHAEL,
WHO KNEW THAT FUND-RAISERS,
A PASSION OF HER MOTHER'S,
WERE SOMETHING
THAT MAEBY WOULD AVOID.
AND LATER,
AT THE COURTHOUSE--
- GOOD AFTERNOON.
- THANK GOD.
SO DID YOU READ THE PLEA?
WE'VE GOT MINUTES HERE,
NOT HOURS.
- I DID READ IT. MOST OF IT.
UM, I DEFINITELY--
DEFINITELY READ THIS, UH--
THE FIRST PART OF THIS FIRST,
UH, SECTION.
UH, NO.
DID NOT READ IT.
- OH, COME ON, MICHAEL.
HOW MANY TIMES
ARE YOU GOING TO SCREW UP...
BEFORE THE REST
OF THIS FAMILY SEES YOU
FOR THE SCREWUP YOU ARE?
- I'M NOT THE LAWYER.
ALL RIGHT?
WHY DIDN'T YOU READ IT?
- EXCUSE ME. I GOT BUSY
WITH MY OTHER CLIENTS.
- WHAT OTHER CLIENTS?
- HE DOESN'T KNOW
ABOUT THE DIVORCE?
- IT'S AN ANNULMENT.
- OH, I LOOKED INTO THAT TOO.
YOU CAN ONLY GET AN ANNULMENT
IF YOU HAVEN'T CONSUMMATED
THE MARRIAGE FIRST.
- WELL, I GUESS
I'LL JUST STAY MARRIED THEN,
BECAUSE WE ALL KNOW THAT
I CLOSED THAT DEAL, RIGHT?
[narrator]
BUT HE REALLY DIDN'T.
- HE WAS TALKING
ABOUT MY DIVORCE.
- YOUR WHAT?
- YOU AND DAD
ARE GETTING DIVORCED?
- OH, DON'T WORRY, SWEETIE.
NO ONE IS FIGHTING OVER YOU.
AND DON'T WORRY ABOUT
BARRY READING THE PLEA.
WE'LL LET YOUR FATHER
ROT IN PRISON.
- TAKE THE PLEA.
WE'RE TAKING THE PLEA!
- WE'RE GOING TO TRIAL,
YOU'RE GOING TO LOSE, AND
YOU'RE GOING TO STAY IN THERE.
- THAT'S ENOUGH, MOM.
- FOR HIM? NOTHING'S ENOUGH.
YOU'D THINK
A MAN LOCKED UP IN PRISON
WOULD BE ABLE TO ABSTAIN.
YOUR FATHER,
WITH HIS DISGUSTING TWEAKING!
I COULDN'T BREAST-FEED
ANY OF YOU KIDS
BECAUSE OF THAT MAN!
- AWW!
- SHH.,
- THEY STILL LOOK FABULOUS.
- LUCILLE, FOR GOD'S SAKES.
SHE WAS AN INFORMANT.
SHE WAS
WORKING FOR THE GOVERNMENT.
THE ONLY THING I WAS PUMPING HER
FOR WAS INFORMATION, HONEY.
- AN INFORMANT.
DAD, ARE YOU CRAZY?
YOU'RE
GONNA BLOW THIS WHOLE CASE.
- IT'S BLOWN. IT'S OVER.
IT'S DEAD. TAKE THE PLEA.
GET ME OUT THERE.
- LETS TAKE THE PLEA, OKAY?
LOOK. IT'S SO NICE AND THICK.
- OH, GEORGE, I SHOULD HAVE
NEVER DOUBTED YOU.
EVEN WHEN YOU SLEPT
WITH MY SISTER,
IT WAS FOR A GOOD REASON.
- GOT HER TO STOP DRINKING,
DIDN'T IT?
- ALL RIGHT, LISTEN.
THIS IS
ALL GETTING A LITTLE CRAZY.
WE CANNOT ACCEPT THEIR
CONDITIONS IF WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THEIR CONDITIONS ARE.
- DO YOU WANNA READ IT?
UH, NO. IT IS THICK.
WHY DON'T WE JUST TAKE IT?
- I COULD KISS YOU ON THE--
[beep]
- WELL, LET'S-- WHAT?
[narrator]
AND SO THE FAMILY GATHERED
IN THE COURTROOM...
TO ANNOUNCE THEIR DECISION.
- ALL RISE.
THE COURT IS NOW IN SESSION.
THE HONORABLE LIONEL PING
PRESIDING.
- OH, WE'VE GOT PING AGAIN.
- PLEASE BE SEATED.
THE PROSECUTION
HAS OFFERED A PLEA?
- WE HAVE, YOUR HONOR.
- WE'VE GOT LIZER.
[narrator]
YES, MAGGIE WAS
THE MOST FEARED PROSECUTOR
IN ALL OF ORANGE COUNTY.
- AND, THEREFORE,
I WOULD LIKE TO BRING
YOUR ATTENTION TO EXHIBIT "A."
[narrator]
NOT BECAUSE SHE WAS
A PARTICULARLY ADEPT LAWYER,
BUT BECAUSE SHE WON
THE SYMPATHY NOT ONLY
OF THE JURY AND THE JUDGE--
- AND WAS THAT MAN IN THE ROOM,
NOT YOU, DOCTOR?
[narrator]
BUT OFTEN TIMES,
THE DEFENDANTS THEMSELVES.
- I-- I WAS IN THAT ROOM.
- IS THE DEFENSE
READY TO RESPOND?
- WHAT ARE YOU HIDING FROM?
- [whispering]
YOU'VE GOT TO CALL THIS OFF.
YOU GOTTA GET MORE TIME.
GET MORE TIME. SHE CAN SMELL.
SHE SMELLS EVERYTHING.
- OBJECTION!
- WHAT?
- WE HAVEN'T READ IT.
IT'S VERY LONG, YOUR HONOR.
- [whispers]
SIT DOWN!
- WE HAVEN'T READ IT.
WE'RE GONNA GET TO IT.
I'M GONNA START RIGHT NOW.
- THAT'S THE BLIND CHICK
YOU SLEPT WITH?
MICHAEL, YOU'RE IN BED
WITH THE PROSECUTION?
- IT'S GENIUS.
YOU CAN GET
ALL THE INFORMATION WE NEED.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
HOW DO WE KNOW IT'S NOT A TRAP?
MAYBE SHE'S SETTING YOU UP.
- IT'S NOT A SETUP, OKAY?
SHE GAVE ME HER REAL NAME.
SHE SAID THAT SHE WAS A LAWYER.
I'M THE ONE THAT LIED TO HER.
I GOTTA GO TALK TO HER.
- NO!
- NO, MICHAEL!
YOU CAN SAVE THIS FAMILY.
PLEASE!
DO THE RIGHT THING HERE.
STRING THIS BLIND GIRL ALONG
SO THAT DAD DOESN'T HAVE TO
PAY HIS DEBT TO SOCIETY.
- THE SOLUTION
TO ALL OUR PROBLEMS
IS STARING YOU RIGHT IN THE FACE
AND IT CAN'T EVEN SEE YOU.
- I GOTTA GO TALK TO HER.
- [sighs]
YEAH, I BETTER
GET BACK TO THE WIFE.
- I THINK I'M GOING TO
TAKE A SCENIC DRIVE DOWN
TO THE CITY OF INDUSTRY.
[narrator]
AND GEORGE MICHAEL WENT TO
THE FUND-RAISER...
FOR THE SICK STUDENT
MAEBY HAD MENTIONED,
BUT WAS SURPRISED
NOT TO SEE MAEBY THERE.
- WE HAVE BEEN BLESSED TO HAVE
IN OUR MIDST A CHILD WHO HAS
SHOWN US THE MEANING OF COURAGE.
NOW LET'S SHOW HER
THE MEANING OF CHARITY.
PLEASE WELCOME--
SURELY FUNKE!
[narrator]
AND THAT'S WHEN
GEORGE MICHAEL REALIZED...
MAEBY HAD BEEN MAKING MONEY
BY PRETENDING TO BE
TWO TWIN GIRLS--
- MAEBY?
[narrator]
ONE OF WHOM WAS ILL.
- [coughing]
- SOMEBODY
GET HER A CUPCAKE!
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL WENT TO MAGGIE'S
DETERMINED TO TELL THE TRUTH.
- WHAT A SURPRISE.
COME ON IN.
- HEY, I'M IN.
HELLO. SORRY.
- OH. HEY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GOING TO BE MY READER.
- YEAH?
OH, YOU'RE WORKING?
- YEAH, I GOT A BREAK.
I WASN'T PREPARED,
THANKS TO YOU.
- MM.
[chuckles]
- WHAT ABOUT YOU?
DON'T TELL ME ANOTHER PIRATE
IS STILL ROAMING THE HIGH SEAS.
[laughs]
- UH, HEY. YOU KNOW,
LET'S MAKE A DEAL.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THIS
ANYMORE, CAUSE I'M GONNA
START LAUGHING OUT LOUD.
- OKAY, THAT'S GONNA
HELP ME SO MUCH.
- ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO SIT DOWN.
SO, UH, MAGGIE.
[clears throat]
- YEAH?
- I AM NOT TRYING A CASE.
- THAT'S FANTASTIC!
THEY SETTLED. GREAT.
- WELL--
- LISTEN, I KNOW
I SHOULDN'T DO THIS, BUT--
BUT I AM SO BEHIND,
AND I REALLY DO FEEL
AS IF I CAN TRUST YOU.
- YEAH?
WHAT IS THIS?
- WELL, YOU OUGHT TO KNOW.
YOU CAN SEE.
[laughs]
- [contrived laughter ]
MAGGIE!
WHAT IS IT?
SERIOUSLY.
- WELL, BASICALLY,
IT'S AN OVERVIEW
OF THE GOVERNMENT'S CASE
AGAINST THE BLUTH FAMILY.
IT'S A SUMMARY OF ABSOLUTELY
EVERYTHING WE'VE GOT.
- AND YOU'RE JUST GOING
TO GIVE IT TO ME?
- YOU'RE A LAWYER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DO WE HAVE A CASE?
- [mouthing words]
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MAEBY ATTEMPTS
TO DEPOSIT HER CHECK.
GOB ADAPTS TO MARRIED LIFE.
- UNBELIEVABLE!
THE SEAL DEAL FELL THROUGH.
THREE OF THE SEALS DIED
ON THEIR WAY TO CHAD.
HOW AM I EVER GONNA FIND
A MARITIME LAWYER?
- I'M SORRY,
DID YOU SAY "SEALS"?
- YES!
I TRADE TRAINED
SEALS FOR A LIVING.
DO YOU EVER LISTEN?
- DO YOU EVER STOP TALKING?
[narrator]
TOBIAS IS SENT TO BREAK
INTO MAGGIE'S HOUSE
TO STEAL EVIDENCE.
ONLY TO DISCOVER
THAT SHE'S NOT BLIND.