narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
AGAINST HIS BETTER JUDGMENT,
MICHAEL HAD RECENTLY SET OUT
TO HAVE AN UNCOMPLICATED
ONE-NIGHT STAND WITH THIS WOMAN.
AND AT HIS BROTHER'S SUGGESTION,
HE GAVE A FALSE IDENTITY.
- CHARETH CUTESTORY.
narrator: AND WHAT STARTED
AS A NIGHT OF PASSION
WITH NO STRINGS ATTACHED,
GOT COMPLICATED
THE NEXT MORNING
WHEN MICHAEL FOUND OUT
SHE WAS BLIND.
HE DECIDED TO KEEP SEEING HER
SO AS NOT TO APPEAR SUPERFICIAL.
- IF IT'S A ONE-NIGHT STAND,
I'M NOT VERY GOOD AT IT.
- [chuckles] WOW.
BUT AREN'T YOU BUSY WITH
THE TRIAL AND EVERYTHING?
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
THE WOMAN ALSO TURNED OUT TO BE
HIS FATHER'S PROSECUTOR.
AND SO MICHAEL WENT TO
MAGGIE'S TO REVEAL HIS IDENTITY.
BUT BEFORE HE COULD--
- IT'S AN OVERVIEW
OF THE GOVERNMENT'S CASE
AGAINST THE BLUTH FAMILY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DO WE HAVE A CASE?
[mouthing words]
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL'S SON, GEORGE MICHAEL,
DISCOVERED THAT HIS COUSIN
MAEBY
HAD BEEN LIVING
A DOUBLE LIFE.
- [coughing]
- MAEBY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU KNOW, I STILL DON'T GET WHY
YOU'RE PRETENDING
TO BE TWO PEOPLE,
AND WHY IS ONE OF YOU SICK?
- HEY, YOU DON'T GET GIANT
CHECKS IF YOU'RE HEALTHY.
- PLEASE WELCOME SURELY FUNKE.
- PLUS, WHO'S GOING TO
GET MAD AT THE DYING GIRL?
- SURELY'S DYING?
- I FIGURE I'LL KILL HER OFF
JUST BEFORE GRADUATION.
JUST SO EVERYONE
GETS REALLY SAD BEFORE PROM.
- MAEBY, SOMEONE'S
GOING TO GET HURT.
NOT TO MENTION IT'S KIND OF
DISRESPECTFUL
FOR KIDS
WHO ACTUALLY HAVE THIS.
- NOT A LOT OF KIDS
HAVE B.S. THESE DAYS.
- WHAT DOES THAT STAND FOR?
- I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S B.S.
narrator: MICHAEL WRESTLED
WITH THE DILEMMA
OF WHETHER HE SHOULD LOOK
AT THE EVIDENCE FILE
OF THE CASE
AGAINST HIS FATHER.
- MICHAEL.
- HEY, GOB.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU WEARING?
- WHAT? OH, THIS--
THE WIFE LIKES ME
IN BRIGHT SWEATERS.
narrator: GOB, IN A SERIES
OF ESCALATING DARES,
RECENTLY GOT MARRIED TO
A WOMAN
HE HAD ONLY KNOWN
FOR AN EVENING.
- YOUR WIFE?
SHE'S STILL YOUR WIFE?
- WELL, I WENT TO
BREAK UP WITH HER LAST NIGHT,
BUT MY TIMING WAS NOT GREAT.
- SO I THINK WE SHOULD TALK.
- MY PARENTS
ARE GETTING A DIVORCE.
[crying]
WHY AREN'T YOU WEARING
THAT SWEATER I BOUGHT YOU?
WHAT, YOU DON'T LIKE IT?
- NO. OF COURSE I LIKE IT.
JUST BECAUSE I LIKE IT
DOESN'T MEAN I HAVE TO WEAR IT.
I DON'T WEAR EVERYTHING I LIKE
EVERY DAY.
- WHY DON'T WE
JUST GET A DIVORCE?
EVERYBODY ELSE IS.
- NO! WE'RE NOT
GETTING DIVORCED.
SHE REALLY WANTS TO
STAY TOGETHER, SO--
- WELL, LEAST YOU FINALLY
CONSUMMATED IT, HUH?
- [laughs]
"CONSUMMATED."
WHAT IS UP WITH
THAT "PROSECUTIE"?
- [groans]
- I HOPE YOU DIDN'T
BREAK UP WITH HER?
- NO, I DIDN'T.
AND TO MAKE MATTERS WORSE,
SHE GAVE ME THIS.
IT'S A SUMMARY OF THE EVIDENCE
THAT THEY HAVE AGAINST DAD.
- OKAY, MICHAEL.
THIS MAKES MATTERS BETTER.
LET'S JUST DESTROY IT
AND MOVE ON WITH OUR LIVES.
- THIS IS NOT
THE ACTUAL EVIDENCE.
IT'S JUST A LIST OF
THE EVIDENCE.
AND JUDGING BY THE AMOUNT
OF BOXES SHE HAS IN HER PLACE,
I HAVE A FEELING THERE'S A LOT.
- A FEELING?
OH, DON'T TELL ME YOU WON'T OPEN
IT ON ETHICAL GROUNDS?
- I'M NOT SURE
WHAT I'M GOING TO DO.
- WHAT IS WITH THE INSANE
MORAL CODE IN THIS FAMILY?
- YES, WE DID IT.
WE'RE GETTING RID
OF THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
YOU KNOW, THE GRANITE ONES
IN FRONT OF THE COURTHOUSE.
YOU KNOW, ALL IT TOOK
WAS THE THREAT OF A LAWSUIT.
- YOU'RE INVOLVED WITH
THOSE PROTESTERS NOW?
WHEN DID THAT HAPPEN?
- OH, WHO CAN REMEMBER.
narrator: LINDSAY'S INVOLVEMENT
BEGAN HOURS BEFORE
WHEN, LEAVING THE PLEA HEARING,
SHE FIRST DETERMINED
THE TEN COMMANDMENTS
DIDN'T BELONG THERE.
- AND THEY WON'T EVEN ALLOW
ME ONE LOUSY CIGARETTE!
- [gasps]
OH.
HONEY, THEY'RE JUST HEELS.
THEY CAN ONLY SUPPORT
SO MUCH WEIGHT.
- I'VE ALWAYS
BEEN VERY PASSIONATE
ABOUT THE SEPARATION
OF CHURCH AND STATE.
- WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH THEM?
- OH, I DON'T KNOW.
GIVE 'EM TO A SCHOOL.
- CAN WE LET ANOTHER FAMILY
BRING DOWN THE TEN COMMANDMENTS?
THIS FAMILY'S ALREADY DONE
MORE THAN ITS SHARE.
- OH, NOW YOU LOVE
THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
AND YET, YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO SO CONVENIENTLY FORGOT
"THOU SHALT PROTECT THY FATHER,
AND HONOR NO ONE ABOVE HIM
UNLESS IT BEITH ME--
THY SWEET LORD."
- I'M NOT SURE THAT ONE
MADE IT DOWN THE MOUNTAIN, GOB.
- I TOLD YOU SOMEONE
WOULD GET HURT.
- YEAH, WELL, IF I KNEW
IT WAS GOING TO BE YOU,
I WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN
SO WORRIED.
- HEY, WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
- HE WAS TRYING TO HELP SOME
HANDICAPPED GIRL
UP TO THE BLEACHERS,
AND HE FELL.
- IT'S JUST A SPRAIN.
BUT AT LEAST
IT'S LEGITIMATE.
- AH, LE CLUMSY ADOLESCENCE.
IT'S A PHASE
WE'VE ALL BEEN THROUGH.
EXCEPT FOR ME.
I WAS LIKE A CAT.
I ALWAYS ENDED UP ON ALL FOURS.
LIKE A CAT.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
THEY DON'T HAVE RAMPS
AT YOUR SCHOOL?
- WELL, NOT UP THE BLEACHERS.
- YOU SHOULD THREATEN TO SUE.
IT'S FREE IF IT'S JUST
A THREAT, YOU KNOW.
- HEY, THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
- ALL RIGHT,
NO ONE'S GONNA SUE ANYBODY.
I'M NOT GONNA HAVE MY SON
START ABUSING THE LEGAL SYSTEM
LIKE THE REST OF THIS FAMILY.
AFTER ALL, WE'RE GONNA NEED IT
FOR YEARS TO COME.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN MICHAEL DECIDED
TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
- SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DO WE HAVE A CASE AGAINST
THIS IDIOT FAMILY OR WHAT?
- WELL, THAT'S ACTUALLY WHY
I WANTED TO TALK TO YOU, MAGGIE.
YOU SEE, UH, IT TURNS OUT
THAT I AM ACTUALLY
ONE OF THOSE IDIOTS.
I MIGHT EVEN BE THE MAIN IDIOT.
WELL, I'M NOT THE MAIN IDIOT,
BUT I'M THE IDIOT IN CHARGE.
YEAH. I'M MICHAEL BLUTH.
OKAY?
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
I NEVER OPENED UP THIS FOLDER.
AND IF YOU COULD SEE MY FACE,
UH, YOU'D SEE HOW SORRY I AM
THAT I LIED TO YOU.
- YOU FEEL SINCERE.
DAMN IT.
I HAVE SPENT THE LAST FIVE HOURS
HATING YOU
EVER SINCE I FOUND OUT YOU WERE
MICHAEL BLUTH IN COURT.
- WHAT? HOW DID YOU KNOW?
- I'M BLIND, MICHAEL.
I'M NOT STUFFED UP.
- YOU SMELLED ME.
- I SMELLED YOU, BABY.
- MAGGIE, WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL ME AT YOUR HOUSE?
AND WHY DID YOU GIVE ME
THIS FOLDER?
- I WAS MANIPULATING YOU.
THIS ISN'T THE REAL LIST.
THIS IS A WISH LIST.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU SET ME UP.
- WELL, YOU LIED TO ME.
CHARETH CUTESTORY?
- I KNOW."THOU SHALT NOT
MAKE UP A NAME IN VAIN."
BUT, YOU KNOW,
I WALKED INTO THAT COURT.
AND I SAW YOU THERE,
AND--THIS CAN'T HAPPEN, RIGHT?
- YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT
THIS CAN'T HAPPEN.
LOOK AT ME.
THIS COULD GET ME--
ARE YOU ACTUALLY LOOKING AT ME?
- YES, I AM.
- OKAY. I COULD GET
DISBARRED FOR THIS.
AND YOUR DAD WOULD HAVE TO
SPEND TONS MORE TIME IN PRISON.
I GOTTA TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THE THING THAT REALLY
GETS TO ME IS
THAT I KEEP HEARING THAT MICHAEL
BLUTH IS SO--[bleep] CUTE.
- WELL, I KNOW MAGGIE LIZER
IS...ADORABLE.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE MISSING.
- REALLY?
- REALLY.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
- I GUESS WE'RE JUST GONNA
HAVE TO GO OUR SEPARATE WAYS
AND AGREE TO NEVER
SPEAK ABOUT THIS AGAIN.
- THAT IS PROBABLY BEST, HUH?
- LOOK, THE LEAST YOU CAN DO
IS BUY ME A DRINK.
- HMM. YEAH. I'LL STAY
FOR ONE DRINK.
[Maggie whooping]
narrator: THE NEXT MORNING,
MICHAEL, ONCE AGAIN,
FOUND HIMSELF AT MAGGIE'S.
AND ONCE AGAIN, BERATED HIMSELF
FOR THE MISTAKE.
- OH, NO.
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE AT
THE PRISON TO TALK TO MY DAD
IN HALF AN HOUR.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE DID THIS AGAIN.
- IT WAS SO STUPID.
- INCREDIBLY STUPID.
IT'S LIKE WE'RE MAKING
NAUGHTY SEX EVEN NAUGHTIER.
[both panting]
- OH, NO. I WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
AT THE PRISON TO TALK TO MY DAD
A HALF AN HOUR AGO.
- OH, THIS IS BAD.
THIS IS REALLY BAD.
THIS IS THE SECOND MOST
UNETHICAL THING I'VE EVER DONE.
- WE CANNOT PRETEND THAT
THIS DIDN'T HAPPEN, MAGGIE.
- OR THAT IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
- YOU THINK IT'S GONNA
HAPPEN AGAIN?
- YOU TELL ME.
- LET'S JUST ASSUME THAT IT WILL
HAPPEN AGAIN AT SOME TIME.
- RIGHT. RIGHT.
- WE JUST NEED TO, YOU KNOW,
ACKNOWLEDGE THIS
AND KEEP IT PRIVATE,
AND I DON'T THINK THAT THERE'S
ANYTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
- RIGHT.
I MEAN, I HAVE A JOB, YOU KNOW?
I'M TRYING TO KEEP A MAN
IN PRISON.
- RIGHT. AND THAT MAN
HAPPENS TO BE MY FATHER.
- [groans]
- THIS COULD GET UGLY.
- WELL, IT'S LIKE
THE TEN COMMANDMENTS SAYING.
"BE TRUE TO THINE OWN SELF,
AND TO THINE OWN SELF--"
- "BE TRUE." YEAH.
NUMBER SEVEN.
- WE'LL JUST HAVE TO
KEEP IT A SECRET.
- OUR SECRET.
- OUR DIRTY LITTLE SECRET.
- I THINK I'M READY NOW.
- ALL RIGHT.
- OKAY.
narrator:
32 MINUTES EARLIER,
GOB, LUCILLE, AND BARRY
MET WITH GEORGE SR.
- WHERE DID YOU GET THIS?
- THEY DON'T CALL ME A SLEIGHT-
OF-HAND ARTIST FOR NOTHING.
narrator: GOB HAD SWITCHED
OUT THE FILE
WHILE HIS SIBLINGS
DISCUSSED THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
- I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
VERY PASSIONATE
ABOUT THE SEPARATION
OF CHURCH AND STATE.
- WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH THEM?
- GIVE 'EM TO A SCHOOL.
- CAN WE LET ANOTHER FAMILY
BRING DOWN THE TEN COMMANDMENTS?
THIS FAMILY'S ALREADY DONE
MORE THAN ITS SHARE.
- NOW YOU LOVE
THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
APPARENTLY, THERE ARE BOXES
OF IT AT THE PROSECUTOR'S HOUSE.
I TRACKED DOWN THE ADDRESS,
AND YOU SHOULD BE
THANKING ME FOR THIS.
MICHAEL DIDN'T WANT YOU
TO HAVE IT.
[mocking] MR. MORAL.
- MM. YEAH, WE DID SOMETHING
RIGHT THERE, HUH?
- SO WHAT DO YOU THINK, BARRY?
- I-I HAVEN'T READ IT.
I HAD A REALLY INTERESTING
DATE LAST NIGHT.
A WOMAN WHO
ACTUALLY WORKS TWO JOBS.
- WELL, IT CERTAINLY LOOKS LIKE
THEY'VE GOT A LOT ON US.
- MM-HMM.
- UH, YOU.
I WAS RAISING THE CHILDREN.
- WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU RAISED CHILDREN?
- EXCUSE ME?
I'VE GOT TWO IN THE WAITING ROOM
RIGHT THIS MOMENT.
narrator:
IN FACT, BUSTER AND ANNYONG,
LUCILLE'S NEWLY ADOPTED
KOREAN CHILD, WERE WAITING.
- WOW. I WONDER WHAT THEY'RE
TALKING ABOUT IN THERE?
- THEY DON'T TELL YOU
ANYTHING, HUH?
- THEY TELL ME THINGS.
IT DOESN'T MATTER THOUGH,
BECAUSE DAD IS GONNA BE
IN HERE A LONG TIME.
[chuckles]
- NO.
WE HAVE COURT DAY TODAY.
THEY TAKE PLEA.
DADDY COME HOME.
YOU OUT.
narrator: ANNYONG HAD HIT A
NERVE, AND BUSTER RECALLED
THAT RIGHT BEFORE
GEORGE SR.'s ARREST,
HE'D MADE A SIMILAR THREAT.
- I SAID HE COULD WEAR THAT TIE.
IT LOOKS BETTER ON HIM.
- NO, NO. LET ME
HELP YOU WITH THAT, SON.
- OH.
- HEY, ENJOY YOURSELF TONIGHT,
BECAUSE YOU ARE OUT OF HERE.
I'M NOT GONNA SPEND MY
RETIREMENT
WATCHING YOU
WIPE YOUR NOSE ON YOUR SLEEVE.
- I CAN'T BREATHE, DAD.
- NEITHER CAN I.
- [whimpers]
- I HAVEN'T SEEN
HALF THIS STUFF,
BUT THEY'VE GOT THESE
KIND OF DOCUMENTS, UH,
WE'VE GOTTA GET RID OF THIS.
- IF YOU'RE THINKING OF
STEALING THE EVIDENCE,
THAT IS A VERY BIG OFFENSE.
I-I THINK I'M GONNA SAY
THAT I SIGNED MYSELF OUT
ABOUT 10 MINUTES AGO.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU CAN'T AFFORD TO GET CAUGHT.
I DON'T NEED MY LAWYER
IN PRISON.
WE'LL HAVE GOB
BREAK IN.
- WELL, GEE, DAD,
I'VE GOT A WIFE NOW.
I DON'T THINK THAT I CAN
AFFORD TO GET CAUGHT EITHER.
- GOOD POINT.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO
CHANGE OUT OF THAT SWEATER.
- TELL ME AGAIN
WHY THIS ISN'T WRONG.
- LOOK. WE ARE JUST--
WE'RE TWO ADULTS.
WE'VE GOT ABSOLUTELY NOTHING--
COPS. HIDE.
- MS. LIZER.
IT'S OFFICER KELLEY.
- OH, HI.
- YOUR OFFICE HAS ASKED ME
TO COME PICK YOU UP.
IT'S A SURPRISE.
I JUST WINKED.
IT'S A SURPRISE WITNESS.
- OH, GREAT.
UM--
- HOW ARE WE DOING?
- I'LL JUST PUT MY DOG INSIDE,
AND THEN I WILL BE
RIGHT WITH YOU.
- I'LL TAKE THE DOG, OKAY?
I'VE ALREADY MISSED MY MEETING.
YOU GO AHEAD.
- JUST PUT HIM
THROUGH THE DOGGY DOOR.
- OKAY.
- AND, UH,
I'LL SEE YOU IN COURT.
- YEAH.
MY DAD'S NOT GONNA
PUT HIMSELF IN PRISON FOR LIFE.
- YEAH.
- BYE. KISS.
- OH.
narrator: AND GOB
DECIDED TO PASS OFF
HIS BREAK-IN ASSIGNMENT
TO TOBIAS.
- HEY, THERE'S THE CAT.
SORRY YOU COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
DOWN AT THE PRISON WITH US.
DAD WAS ASKING ALL ABOUT YOU.
- OH. I DOUBT THAT VERY MUCH.
- LOOK, I'M NOT GONNA
LIE TO YOU.
HE FEELS YOU'VE BEEN SUCKING
OFF THIS FAMILY FAR TOO LONG.
IF YOU DON'T START PULLING
YOUR WEIGHT AROUND HERE,
IT'S GONNA BE SHAPE UP
OR SHIP UP.
- YOU KNOW, TRY AS I MIGHT,
I CANNOT SEEM TO
IMPRESS THAT MAN.
- ISN'T THAT FUNNY?
[chuckles]
I'M ABOUT TO
KNOCK HIS SOCKS OFF AGAIN.
YEAH, I'M GONNA BREAK INTO
THIS HOUSE
THAT'S GOT A BUNCH
OF EVIDENCE IN IT.
JUST TO BORROW IT.
ENSURE HIS FREEDOM FOREVER.
BUT, IT'S A TOUGH JOB.
MIGHT REQUIRE SOME AGILITY.
- [whispering]
THIS KIND OF AGILITY?
- LET'S GO, LITTLE MAN.
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
HAD DECIDED TO SEE WHAT LIFE
IN MAGGIE'S WORLD WAS LIKE.
- ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
OKAY.
- THIS GUY'S THE REAL DEAL.
HE'S ON THE INSIDE.
BUT HE'S GOT SOME DEMANDS.
- THIS COULD BE
THE BREAK WE WANTED.
- THIS IS
DISTRICT ATTORNEY LIZER.
- ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- UH, I-I WANT IMMUNITY
FOR ME AND MY MOM,
AND I WANT
MY DAD TO STAY IN PRISON.
ALSO, CAN YOU SEND
ANNYONG BACK TO KOREA?
- HUH?
- HEY!
- JUSTICE!
[horn honking]
[tires screeching]
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MAGGIE'S INTERROGATION OF
BUSTER WAS PROVING FRUITLESS.
- DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT YOUR FATHER'S TRIPS
OVERSEAS?
- I KNEW I'D HAVE A FUN TIME
AT HOME ALONE WITH MOM.
- FINE. DID YOU EVER SEE HIM
RETURN FROM THESE TRIPS
WITH ANYTHING UNUSUAL?
- YEAH.
HE CAME BACK HOME ONCE
WITH A BLACK STATUE
WITH AN ERECT PENIS.
IT STAYED IN OUR LIVING ROOM
UNTIL MY AUNT OBJECTED.
- WHAT ABOUT
BUSINESS ASSOCIATES?
- I HAVE NONE.
- ALL RIGHT.
THIS GUY'S WASTING OUR TIME.
TAKE AWAY HIS GRILLED CHEESE.
- [stammering]
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
IF IT'S EVIDENCE YOU WANT,
I KNOW WHERE THEY KEEP IT.
ACCORDING TO MY BROTHER,
THERE ARE BOXES OF EVIDENCE
IN A HOUSE ON SCENIC VIEW DRIVE.
- ISN'T THAT WHERE YOU LIVE?
- YEAH.
AND I'M HEADED THERE NOW.
narrator: TOBIAS, MEANWHILE,
HAD USED HIS CATLIKE AGILITY
TO GET THE EVIDENCE
AT MAGGIE'S HOUSE.
- THE CAT IS IN.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY, IT WAS
JUST AS MAGGIE CAME HOME.
[sniffing]
[sniffs]
IS THERE SOMEONE HERE?
narrator:
TOBIAS, CONCERNED ABOUT
MAGGIE'S
HEIGHTENED SENSE OF SMELL,
SET OFF TO CLOAK HIMSELF
IN HER SCENT.
- AND MICHAEL WAS AT
THE VET'S OFFICE.
- JUSTICE IS FINE.
- GREAT.
- ALTHOUGH, DRESSING HIM UP
LIKE A SEEING-EYE DOG
SEEMS A LITTLE CRUEL.
- CRUEL?
- WELL, YEAH,
BECAUSE HE CAN'T SEE.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- MR. BLUTH,
JUSTICE IS BLIND.
- JUSTICE
CANNOT BE BLIND, DOC.
HE'S GOT A HANDLE
AND EVERYTHING.
COME ON, BOY.
MAYBE HIS PERIPHERAL
ISN'T GREAT,
BUT HE'S BEEN LEADING
A BLIND WOMAN AROUND.
- I THINK SHE'S BEEN
LEADING HIM AROUND.
- BUT THAT WOULD MEAN THAT
MAGGIE ISN'T BLIND.
narrator:
IN FACT, MAGGIE WASN'T BLIND,
BUT HAD BEEN PRETENDING
TO BE...
- SON OF A BITCH.
narrator: SINCE SHE FOUND IT
HELPFUL IN TAKING THE LSATs.
- "D." "B" PLACES FOURTH.
- "A"?
narrator:
FINDING IT A TREMENDOUS BOON
TO HER PROFESSIONAL LIFE,
MAGGIE CONTINUED THE RUSE.
- I SUBMIT INTO EVIDENCE
THIS WINE GLASS
WITH THE DEFENDANT'S
FINGERPRINTS.
[glass shatters]
- DON'T WORRY. YOU'RE SO AHEAD.
- [clicks tongue, chuckles]
narrator: HER ABILITY TO SEE,
HOWEVER,
WAS CURRENTLY PROVING
A DISADVANTAGE,
AS SHE COULDN'T REVEAL TO THE
MAN SHE RECOGNIZED AS TOBIAS
THAT SHE KNEW HE WAS THERE
WITHOUT BETRAYING HER SECRET.
AND TOBIAS WAS FINDING HER
AN UNCANNILY DIFFICULT
BLIND GIRL TO OUTMANEUVER.
THEIR GAME OF CAT AND MOUSE
CONTINUED.
UNTIL MICHAEL SHOWED UP
TO RETURN JUSTICE.
- OH, JUSTICE, WHAT IS IT, BOY?
WHAT IS IT?
IS THERE SOME JACKASS
IN MY BATHROBE?
[spraying]
[both screaming]
- OH! I CAN'T SEE!
narrator: AND LATER, THE FAMILY
GATHERED AT THE COURTHOUSE
TO RESPOND TO THE PLEA OFFER.
- THEY DON'T HAVE A CASE
AGAINST US.
I TOOK CARE OF EVERYTHING.
- SOMETHING SMELLS WONDERFUL.
- WELL, THANK YOU.
WOULD THAT I COULD SAY THAT
I WORE IT TO IMPRESS YOU,
BUT, NO, I'M AFRAID IT'S
MERELY A CLOAKING AGENT
FROM A SADLY BLUNDEROUS
AFTERNOON.
- WHO ELSE HAVE WE GOT?
WHAT ABOUT BUSTER?
WORST-CASE SCENARIO
HE GETS CAUGHT, NO MORE BUSTER.
- I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S STAYING PUT.
NOT ME. YOU.
- WHAT'S GOTTEN INTO YOU?
HAVE YOU BEEN EATING CHEESE?
narrator:
OUTSIDE THE COURTHOUSE,
SURELY FUNKE
WAS ADDRESSING THE CROWD.
GEORGE MICHAEL PREPARED TO
CONFRONT HER ABOUT IT.
- NOT JUST TO ME, BUT TO ALL
HANDICAPPED KIDS OUT THERE
WHO ARE SICK AND TIRED
OF SITTING IN THE FRONT ROWS
AT BASKETBALL GAMES.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL SPOTTED
HIS FATHER,
AND NOT WANTING TO APPEAR
TO BE ABUSING THE LEGAL SYSTEM,
FOUND A PLACE TO HIDE.
MICHAEL, DETERMINED TO
EXPOSE MAGGIE,
HID TO AVOID
TIPPING HIS HAND.
IT WAS THEN, HOWEVER,
THAT LINDSAY'S ADVOCACY GROUP
HAD THEIR BIG MOMENT.
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I JUST THOUGHT I'D COME DOWN
AND SEE THE FAMILY.
SEE EVERYONE.
- OH.
- THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
- WELL, PAL, YOU DON'T
NEED TO DO THAT.
YOU CAN HEAD ON HOME.
WHY DON'T YOU GO HELP THAT
HANDICAPPED FRIEND OF YOURS?
- SHE KIND OF LIED TO ME.
- I WAS RECENTLY
LIED TO MYSELF.
AND FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH,
GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU CANNOT LET PEOPLE
GET AWAY WITH THAT.
- IT'S JUST SO HARD TO KNOW WHAT
THE RIGHT THING TO DO IS.
- I KNOW IT. IT'S NOT LIKE
THERE'S SOME LIST OF RULES
HANDED DOWN TO US
FROM ON HIGH.
- NO.
- WATCH YOUR HEAD.
[loud crash]
[car alarm blaring]
narrator: SO MICHAEL SET OUT TO
EXPOSE IN COURT
THAT MAGGIE
WASN'T REALLY BLIND.
- SHE'S RIGHT THERE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
- I GOT A PLAN.
- THANK GOD.
- YOUR HONOR, THE PURPOSE
OF A COURT OF LAW
IS TO FIND THE TRUTH,
WHICH IS WHY WITNESSES
SWEAR ON THIS.
AFTER ALL, THEY SAY
JUSTICE IS BLIND.
SURELY, SHE HAS ENOUGH SIGHT
TO CATCH THE TRUTH
BEFORE IT HITS HER
IN THE FACE.
- OBJECTION, YOUR--
- [all gasp]
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
MAGGIE HAD BEEN
TEMPORARILY BLINDED THAT DAY.
- I CAN'T SEE!
- BAILIFF!
- THAT WAS MY PLAN.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
narrator: SO GEORGE MICHAEL
DECIDED TO ONCE AND FOR ALL
PUT AN END TO SURELY FUNKE.
- I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
- AND THIS IS THE MAN
WHO INSPIRED ME.
GEORGE MICHAEL BLUTH.
[scattered applause]
HE IS THE ONE WHO IS
RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE NEW RAMPS
AT OUR SCHOOL.
AND HE WILL CARRY ON MY LEGACY
AND PUT AN END TO B.S.
- SURELY CAN BEAT THIS THING.
[together]
NO MORE B.S. NO MORE B.S.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
REUNITED WITH MAGGIE,
WHO HAD BEEN KICKED
OFF THE CASE.
- I REALLY THOUGHT
YOU WERE LYING TO ME.
I AM SO SORRY.
- MICHAEL, I'VE BEEN DOING
THIS BLIND ACT THING FOR YEARS.
IT'S WACKED.
- ARE YOU GOING TO ADMIT
THAT YOU WERE FAKING IT?
- I THINK I'M GONNA GO FOR
"I WAS STRUCK BY THE BIBLE
AND IT RESTORED MY SIGHT."
[laughs]
SO WHAT ABOUT US?
WE WERE STARTING TO
ESTABLISH SOME TRUST
EXCEPT FOR ALL THE LIES.
- YOU KNOW, I WAS ORIGINALLY
LOOKING FOR SOMETHING
COMPLETELY UNCOMPLICATED.
- YEAH. ME TOO.
FORGET IT.
THIS IS SO OVER.
- YOU KNOW, WE'RE SAYING
GOOD-BYE,
AND THIS IS
ACTUALLY THE FIRST TIME
THAT I FEEL THAT YOU CAN
REALLY SEE ME.
- YEAH.
WE'RE JUST TWO PEOPLE
STARING AT EACH OTHER
FULLY EXPOSED
IN A COURT OF LAW.
- [singing] HEY,
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL MORNING
I WAKE UP
AND LOOK AROUND
- JUSTICE!
[whistles]
smash!
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
BARRY GETS A SIGN
FROM GOD.
- I WILL OBEY YOUR WILL.
I WILL LEAD A GOOD LIFE.
WELL, THE HELL
WITH THIS THEN!
narrator: AND MAGGIE IS REPLACED
WITH A NEW, LESS GENEROUS,
PROSECUTOR.
- I WAS MADE TO UNDERSTAND
THERE WERE GRILLED CHEESE
SANDWICHES HERE.5