[narrator]
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
- THE LOCAL COLLEGES
ARE ON SPRING BREAK,
AND THINGS ARE HEATING UP
IN NEWPORT BEACH.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL WAS OFF
FROM SCHOOL FOR TWO WEEKS...
AND WAS ENJOYING SPENDING TIME
WITH HIS UNCLE.
- I'M INTERCEPTING
SOME TELEPATHIC ENERGY...
THAT'S TELLING ME
IT'S THE EIGHT OF DIAMONDS.
- THAT'S AMAZINGLY CLOSE.
- GEE, I GOT IT WRONG. WELL.
I GUESS YOU WON
THE SHIRT OFF MY BACK.
- OKAY, THAT'S AMAZING.
- IT'S THE QUEEN OF DIAMONDS.
- NO, NO, NO.
I HAD-- BUT IF THAT
HAD BEEN THE ACTUAL CARD,
I'M PRETTY SURE I'D BE
ALMOST TOO BLOWN AWAY.
- YOU KNOW, IT'S A NEW TRICK,
SO I'M STILL KIND OF
TWEAKING MY NIPPLES--
- THE PRESENTATION WAS GREAT.
- HEY. WHOA!
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE, HUH?
GEORGE MICHAEL, YOU SHOULD
GET TO SCHOOL.
- NO, WE'RE OFF FOR TWO WEEKS.
GOB'S TEACHING ME
SOME NEW TRICKS.
- SPRING BREAK!
[grunts]
IT'S MY FAVORITE HOLIDAY.
- NOTHING GETS ME MORE EXCITED.
- I CAN SEE THAT.
YOU MIGHT WANNA
BUTTON THAT SHIRT UP.
- NO, I'M GOOD.
ANYWAY, LISTEN, MICHAEL.
I NEED THE YACHT.
I KIND OF MADE A COMMITMENT.
[narrator]
ONE YEAR EARLIER,
GOB HAD APPEARED...
ON A YOUTH-ORIENTED
MUSIC NETWORK...
WHEN THEY DID A SEGMENT ON
"SPRING BREAK: NEWPORT BEACH."
- NOW THAT I'VE GOTTEN
YOUR ATTENTION,
I'D LIKE TO ANNOUNCE
THAT ONE YEAR FROM TODAY,
I SHALL MAKE THAT
BEAUTIFUL YACHT DISAPPEAR.
[crowd cheering]
- WOW.
HE'S AMAZING.
- HE HASN'T DONE IT, AND YOU'RE
HOLDING A FOUR OF SPADES
IN YOUR HAND.
- I DON'T CARE.
I'M LOVING THE RIDE, YOU KNOW?
- HOW ARE YOU GONNA DO IT?
-WELL, YOU'VE GOT TWO WEEKS OFF.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO FIND OUT.
[chuckling]
MAYBE WE'LL MEET A COUPLE
YOUNG COEDS ALONG THE WAY.
HOW YOUNG IS TOO YOUNG FOR YOU?
-THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN, OKAY?
THERE'S NOT GONNA BE
ANY COEDS.
THERE CERTAINLY ISN'T
GONNA BE ANY MAGIC.
IT IS A PATH TO A LONELY LIFE
WHERE PEOPLE MOCK YOU.
AND YOU DON'T
EVEN REALIZE IT.
- MICHAEL, I'M A MAGI--
OH, I SEE WHAT YOU DID.
- YOU'RE NOT DRESSED YET?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE WORKING
FOR ME TODAY AT THE OFFICE.
- YOU GUYS STAY OPEN
DURING SPRING BREAK?
- WE'RE NOT ORTHODOX.
BUT DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
KITTY'S COMING BACK,
AND IT'S JUST IN TIME.
ALTHOUGH SHE'S CAUSED
NOTHING BUT PROBLEMS
SINCE SHE'S WORKED FOR ME.
[phone ringing]
KITTY, ISN'T THAT YOUR PHONE?
- NO, I'M ON THE PHONE
WITH YOUR DAD.
THAT ONE'S YOUR LINE.
[ringing continues]
- KITTY, THESE ARE NOT
THE FILES I ASKED FOR.
- OH, THEN I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I SHREDDED.
- HAVE YOU HAD A CHANCE
TO TYPE UP THAT REPORT YET?
- NO, I HAVE BEEN GOOGLING
YOUR FATHER.
- SO I'VE HEARD.
- [chuckling]
- SHE'S BEEN OUT FOR TWO WEEKS
WITH THIS CHEST THING,
BUT SHE'S HAD NO PROBLEMS
CASHING THE CHECKS
I'VE BEEN SENDING HER.
- SPEAKING OF WHICH,
HAVE WE GOTTEN ANYTHING
FROM NANA?
- BUSTER GOT A PERFORATED HEART
AND GOB GOT
THAT RECEDING HAIRLINE,
BUT YOU AND I PRETTY MUCH
DODGED THE BULLET.
- NO, I MEANT IN THE MAIL.
SHE USUALLY SENDS CHECKS
FOR MAEBY'S BIRTHDAY.
- THERE'S BEEN CASH COMING IN?
HAVE YOU BEEN HOLDING OUT ON ME?
- NO. NO,
I'VE BEEN INVESTING IT.
LET'S FACE IT.
I'M BETTER WITH MONEY
THAN YOU ARE.
- BETTER AT SPENDING IT.
- OKAY, I TELL YOU WHAT.
I'LL TAKE YOU DOWN TO SEE NANA
IF YOU SPLIT THE MONEY
WITH ME 60/40.
- 55/55.
- DEAL.
- SOUNDS LIKE YOU GUYS ARE
GETTING MORE THAN YOU THINK.
- WE SHOULD GO NOW
BEFORE YOUR DAD GETS BACK.
NO NEED GOING HALFSIES
WITH HIM TOO.
- RIGHT.
[narrator]
IN FACT,
TOBIAS HAD GONE TO PRISON...
TO RESEARCH THE ROLE
OF FRIGHTENED INMATE \#2
FOR A FILM.
THIS CAME AT A BAD TIME
FOR GEORGE SR.,
WHO WAS IN A CONFLICT WITH A
PRISONER NAMED WHITE POWER BILL,
A CONFLICT TOBIAS
INADVERTENTLY HELPED HIM SOLVE.
- I SOLD YOU FOR
A PACK OF CIGARETTES.
- BUT DIDN'T YOU COME HERE
TO RESEARCH THE NATURE OF FEAR?
I CAN'T THINK OF A BETTER
TEACHER THAN WHITE POWER BILL.
HE'S LIKE A MASTER'S COURSE
UNTO HIMSELF.
- SO YOU THINK I'M A COWARD?
- THERE'S ONLY ONE MAN
I'VE EVER CALLED "COWARD".
THAT'S BRIAN DOYLE-MURRAY.
NO.
WHAT I'M CALLING YOU...
IS A TELEVISION ACTOR.
- OUCH.
[narrator]
AND SO TOBIAS
REMAINED IN PRISON...
AS LINDSAY AND MAEBY
ARRIVED AT NANA'S.
[knocking]
- REMEMBER,
SHE'S A VERY OLD WOMAN.
WE'RE GOING TO GET IN,
GET THE CASH AND GET OUT.
- IS THIS WHO I THINK IT IS?
- [together]
NANA!
[narrator]
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE WOMAN WHO NOW LIVED THERE
WAS NOT THEIR NANA.
A FACT THAT TOOK LINDSAY
AND MAEBY AN HOUR AND A HALF
TO ASCERTAIN.
- GO! GO! IT'S NOT HER!
DROP THE PHOTO ALBUM!
WE'RE NOT IN THE PHOTO ALBUM!
- DROP THE PIE!
- [panting]
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL ARRIVED
AT WORK TO FIND KITTY.
- HEY, KITTY,
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
- MUCH BETTER.
MAN, I WAS REALLY
STUFFED UP THERE!
UP HERE, MICHAEL.
UP HERE.
- WHY'D YOU HAVE TO GET SICK
NOW?
WHAT WAS THE RUSH?
[narrator]
IN FACT, IT WAS THE
PREVIOUS YEAR'S SPRING BREAK..
THAT WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR KITTY'S RUSH...
WHEN THE MAKERS
OF THE POPULAR VIDEO SERIES,
GIRLS WITH LOW SELF-ESTEEM,
CHOSE NOT TO INCLUDE HER.
- OKAY, WE GOT
ALL THE GOOD STUFF HERE.
- LET'S JUST SAY
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
A MORE SUCCESSFUL SPRING BREAK.
- "BREAK"? YOU WERE JUST OUT.
- THAT WAS MY SICK LEAVE.
THIS IS VACATION.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT
GOING ON VACATION.
- OH, YES, I ABSOLUTELY AM!
IF YOU NEED ME,
I WILL BE AT SENOR TADPOLES,
HAVING A MARGARITA
MADE IN MY MOUTH.
- NO, NO. HEY.
KITTY, THERE WILL BE NO
MARGARITA IN YOUR MOUTH.
- OH, YES,
THERE ABSOLUTELY WILL BE
A MARGARITA IN MY MOUTH!
SPRING BREAK!
[whooping]
UP HERE, MICHAEL.
UP HERE.
- PUT THE SHIRT BACK DOWN
AND KEEP ON MOVING.
YOU'RE FIRED.
- I WORK FOR YOUR FATHER.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE HIRING
AND FIRING POWER.
- I ABSOLUTELY DO,
AND YOU'RE FIRED.
- I DON'T THINK YOUR FATHER IS
GONNA BE VERY HAPPY ABOUT THIS.
BUT TAKE A GOOD LOOK,
'CAUSE IT'S THE LAST TIME!
- THAT'S THE SEVENTH NIPPLE
I'VE SEEN TODAY.
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL
WAS CALLED TO THE PRISON.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING FIRING KIT?
YOU CAN'T FIRE KITTY.
FIRST OF ALL, YOU DON'T
HAVE HIRING AND FIRING POWER.
- I DO.
AND I HAD TO.
SHE'S CRAZY.
- THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T FIRE HER.
YOU DON'T FIRE CRAZY.
YOU NEVER FIRE CRAZY.
- DAD, SHE'S INCOMPETENT.
SHE'S COMPLETELY UNPROFESSIONAL.
LOOK, SHE JUST CAME BACK FROM
SICK LEAVE, UH, WITH THESE--
OH, MY GOD, YOU PAID
FOR THOSE, DIDN'T YOU?
- YOU GOT CARRIED AWAY.
HELL, I'VE BEEN SO
CORRUPTED BY MY POWER...
THAT I EVEN ENJOYED
FIRING MY OWN TWIN BROTHER.
YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN HIS FACE
WHEN HE WAS BEGGING ME NOT TO.
WELL, HE'S MY TWIN BROTHER.
I CAN SHOW YOU.
[crying, mumbling]
[laughing]
IT WAS FUNNY.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
KITTY HAD ACCESS
TO ALL KINDS OF INFORMATION.
GOD KNOWS WHAT SHE POKED
HER NOSE INTO.
- THERE'S ENOUGH EVIDENCE
ON THIS BOAT TO PUT ME AWAY.
THE ONLY REAL THING
I HAVE--
OH, GOD, THERE'S NOTHING
TO HOLD ON TO DOWN THERE.
YOU'RE LIKE A BOY.
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
- ALL THESE BOOKS ARE COOKED!
[sobbing]
- I'M SORRY.
I GOTTA DO MY JOB.
- AND I GOTTA GET OUT OF PRISON.
NEXT TIME SOMEONE THREATENS ME,
I MAY NOT HAVE
A SON-IN-LAW TO OFFER.
- I CAN'T COME IN HERE
ALL THE T-- "OFFER"?
- I MAY NOT HAVE A SON-IN-LAW
TO OFFER ME COUNSELING.
YOU KNOW, HE SHOULD HAVE
STAYED A SHRINK.
HE'S VERY GIFTED, YOU KNOW.
[narrator]
IN FACT, TOBIAS HAD EVEN
PRODUCED A VIDEOTAPE,
BUT ITS BRIEF SUCCESS
WAS DUE TO ITS MISLEADING NAME.
ONCE THIS WAS DISCOVERED,
ALL BUT 10 OF THE VIDEOS
WERE RETURNED.
- HIRE KITTY BACK, OKAY?
FOR THE COMPANY. NO, NO.
FOR ME, MICHAEL.
[crying]
- IT IS KIND OF A FUNNY FACE.
- OH, COME ON, NOW.
- THERE'S JUST ABSOLUTELY
NO PURSE THAT WILL GO
WITH THIS OUTFIT.
YOU'VE GOT A LITTLE POCKET
THERE, ANNYONG.
- ANNYONG.
- THAT'S NOT GETTING OLD.
[door closes]
- WHERE'S NANA?
- I SENT HER
ON A WONDERFUL CRUISE.
YOU JUST MISSED
A WONDERFUL CALL FROM HER.
SHE JUST CAME BACK FROM
A WONDERFUL COSTUME PARTY
THAT THE CAPTAIN THREW.
SHE GAINED 10 POUNDS--
THERE'S SO MUCH FOOD
ON THAT BOAT.
SHE'S UP TO 74!
IT'S WONDERFUL, JUST WONDERFUL.
[narrator]
IN FACT, LUCILLE'S MOTHER
HAD BEEN DEAD FOR SIX MONTHS.
- SHE TRIED PESTO
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
NINETY-TWO YEARS OLD,
AND SHE NEVER TRIED PESTO.
[narrator]
LUCILLE FEARED THAT THE FAMILY
WOULD COME AFTER THE INHERITANCE
IF THEY FOUND OUT.
- WAS SHE ON THE PHONE, ANNYONG?
- ANNYONG.
- [sighs]
EMERY BOARD.
ISN'T HE GREAT?
AND HE GOES WITH EVERYTHING.
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, GOB WAS ADJUSTING
TO A NEW COMPANION OF HIS OWN.
- THAT'S NOT
THE END OF THE TRICK.
THERE'S A BIG SURPRISE COMING.
- TAKE YOUR T-SHIRT OFF, PLEASE.
- WHAT?
OH, YOU CHANGED THE TRICK.
IT'S A DIFFERENT TRICK.
- IF I ROLL UP THIS T-SHIRT,
PUT IT IN THIS HAT--
- GOB! HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL.
- HANG ON. WE'RE IN
THE MIDDLE OF SOMETHING.
- IF YOU'LL BE SO KIND AS TO
EXPOSE YOUR BREASTS, PLEASE.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO! HEY,
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
[people shouting]
- DAD, IT'S MISDIRECTION.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO KEEP YOUR EYE
ON THE SHIRT IN THE HAT.
- GET DOWNSTAIRS RIGHT NOW.
COME ON.
BUDDY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M DYING TO SEE HOW HE
MAKES THIS YACHT DISAPPEAR.
- HE'S NOT GOING TO MAKE
THE YACHT DISAPPEAR.
I TOLD HIM THAT.
- IT'S DRIVING ME CRAZY.
IT'S LIKE A MIND PUZZLE,
AN AWESOME MIND PUZZLE.
[narrator]
MICHAEL LOOKED AT HIS SON
AND SAW...
THAT HE TRULY WAS INSPIRED
BY HIS UNCLE--
THAT PERHAPS THE BOY
ACTUALLY ADMIRED HIM.
- I GOTTA GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA COME
WORK WITH ME AT THE OFFICE.
GO WAIT IN THE STAIR CAR.
HEY, I WANT YOU
TO EXPLAIN SOMETHING TO ME.
I'M OUT LOOKING FOR KITTY,
AND I FIND MY SON IN THE MIDDLE
OF A GIRLS WITH LOW
SELF-ESTEEM VIDEO.
- DON'T WORRY.
HE'S GONNA
BE COVERED WITH A BLUE DOT.
HE APPROACHED ME.
AND AS FOR KITTY,
I THINK YOU'RE CRAZY
TO HAVE FIRED HER.
WHO KNOWS WHAT KIND
OF INFORMATION SHE HAS.
HE'S MY BROTHER,
AND HE'S NEVER
EVEN SAID "GOOD JOB."
I JUST WANT HIM TO LOVE ME,
YOU KNOW?
- WOW, YOU GET REALLY GIRLIE
AFTER, HUH?
- YEAH, SHE DEFINITELY KNOWS
WAY TOO MUCH.
WELL, GO GET HER.
IT'S THE HOLIDAYS.
I'M SURE SHE'S DOWN
AT SENOR TADPOLES.
- RIGHT.
HAVING A COCKTAIL
MADE IN HER MOUTH.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA GO TAKE CARE OF THAT.
IN THE MEANTIME,
STAY AWAY FROM MY SON.
- WOW, MICHAEL,
I'M REALLY HURT.
IT'S FAMILY.
WHAT'S MORE IMPORTANT
THAN FAMILY, MICHAEL?
THIS YACHT?
- OF COURSE NOT, GOB.
- YOU'D MAKE THE DEAL?
BECAUSE I'D SIGN
OFF ON THAT RIGHT NOW.
I STAY AWAY FROM YOUR SON;
YOU LET ME USE THE YACHT.
- THE HOLIDAYS REALLY BRINGS OUT
THE BEST IN YOU.
- WELL--
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, TOBIAS FOUND
HIS EXPERIENCE AS A THERAPIST.
WAS HELPING HIM DEAL
WITH HIS NEW CELL MATE.
- YES, BUT WHERE DOES
THE HATE COME FROM, BILL?
WHAT CAUSES IT?
- THE JEWS, I GUESS.
- SURE. BUT I THINK YOU NEED
TO LOOK DEEPER.
I THINK THESE ARE ISSUES
OF SELF-ESTEEM.
I KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE.
I KNOW HOW IT FEELS...
TO HAVE A FATHER,
OR, IN MY CASE, A FATHER-IN-LAW,
WHO DOESN'T RESPECT YOU.
"ANYHOO," WE HAVE VERY
LITTLE TIME...
BEFORE THIS, UH, 4:00 POUNDING
YOU PROMISED ME.
I'M GONNA TAKE A SHOT
AT SOMETHING AND SAY...
THAT I THINK YOU HATE
WHITE POWER BILL.
- I HATE YOU!
- YOU HATE WHITE POWER BILL.
- I HATE THE GOVERNMENT!
- I HATE MY FATHER!
[man on p.a.]
RECREATION.
ALL PRISONERS, ONE HOUR.
- GO GET 'EM.
[prisoners chattering]
- I HATE WHITE POWER BILL.
[thud]
- I GOT A PRISONER DOWN!
PRISONER DOWN!
- YOU KILLED HIM.
- WELL, I--
- LIKE DOROTHY.
THE WICKED WITCH IS DEAD.
ALL HAIL DOROTHY!
[applause]
[narrator]
AND AT AN ELEGANT RESTAURANT,
MICHAEL ASKED KITTY
TO COME BACK.
- WHO ARE YOU
ASKING BACK, MICHAEL?
ME? OR THESE?
- I WANT YOU ALL BACK.
I WANT THE WHOLE GANG.
OKAY? PLEASE, KITTY?
I'M TRYING
REAL HARD HERE, YOU KNOW.
CAN WE JUST MAKE BELIEVE
THAT NONE OF THIS EVER HAPPENED
AND JUST START FRESH?
- MICHAEL,
OF COURSE I'LL COME BACK.
'CAUSE I NEVER REALLY LEFT,
BECAUSE WE BOTH KNOW
THAT YOU CAN'T FIRE PEOPLE.
- NO, I DID FIRE YOU,
AND NOW I'M HIRING YOU BACK.
- YOU DON'T HAVE AUTHORITY
OVER ME.
THEY DON'T HAVE NACHOS HERE.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
WHY DON'T WE FORGET IT?
BECAUSE I'VE BEEN TRYING TO BE
VERY, VERY GENEROUS TO YOU,
AND YOU DON'T RESPECT ME,
SO I'M FIRING YOU, OKAY?
YOU ARE FIRED.
- ALL RIGHT, MICHAEL.
BUT I KNOW WHERE THINGS ARE
AND YOU DON'T,
AND YOU ARE ASKING
FOR A WHOLE WORLD OF TROUBLE.
- IF YOU'RE THREATENING ME,
YOU'RE GONNA BE VERY SORRY.
- ARE YOU THREATENING ME?
- YEAH, THAT'S A THREAT.
I'M THREATENING YOU.
- DID YOU HEAR THAT EVERYONE?
MICHAEL BLUTH IS THREATENING ME!
- I'VE GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE.
I'M A PART OF THE STORY.
I CAN'T BE A PART OF THE STORY.
- SAY GOOD-BYE
TO YOUR COMPANY, MICHAEL.
AND SAY GOOD-BYE TO THESE.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
- 'CAUSE IT'S THE LAST TIME.
- A WOMAN SHOWS ALL
DURING A FRACAS...
AT A LOCAL RESTAURANT,
SOURCES SAY.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS WORKING HARDER THAN EVER
OVER HIS SPRING BREAK,
FILLING IN FOR THE NOW
TWICE-FIRED KITTY.
- LOOK AT US WORKING TOGETHER.
YOU GET THE HANG OF THIS,
AND THIS COULD BE YOUR SUMMER.
- WELL I DON'T KNOW, DAD.
I REALLY WANTED TO SEE
GOB'S MAGIC SHOW AND--
- NO, YOU DON'T.
ISN'T THIS MUCH MORE FUN,
WORKING WITH YOUR DAD?
- IT'S JUST,
THERE WAS SOME OTHER--
- YOU GONNA GET THAT?
[phone ringing]
THANKS, LAURA.
- GOOD AFTERNOON.
BLUTH COMPANY.
TALK YOU OFF?
TALK YOU OFF WHAT, POP-POP?
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE, UM--
WHEN'S THAT VOICE GONNA DROP?
WHERE'S KITTY?
- I THINK DAD FIRED HER AGAIN.
HE WANTS TO TALK TO YOU.
- I DON'T WANNA TALK TO HIM.
I MADE MY DECISION,
AND THAT'S THAT.
- OH, YOU HEARD?
YEAH. ALL RIGHT.
- WHAT DID HE SAY?
- WELL, IF I CLEAN IT UP,
IT'S NOT REALLY A SENTENCE.
[narrator]
AND SO, GEORGE SR.
MADE ANOTHER CALL.
- KITTY'S ON THE LOOSE.
I NEED YOU TO MAKE
SOMETHING DISAPPEAR FOR ME.
JUST SOME BOOKS IN THAT COOLER
MARKED "MADDAS."
GREAT.
[narrator]
GEORGE SR. HUNG UP,
CONFIDENT THAT HIS PROBLEMS
WOULD FINALLY BE TAKEN CARE OF.
- HEY, LITTLE JUSTICE.
YOU, UH, PAINTED
YOUR SHOES RED.
- CALL ME THE TIN MAN.
I'M A FRIEND OF DOROTHY'S NOW.
AND SHE WANTS TO SEE YOU.
[narrator]
AND BACK AT THE OFFICE,
LINDSAY ARRIVED
WITH HER DAUGHTER
AND HER MOUNTING SUSPICIONS.
- MOM SAYS SHE
SENT NANA ON A CRUISE.
- YOU'RE STILL ON THIS?
HOW MUCH WAS IN
THOSE BIRTHDAY CARDS?
- IT'S NOT ABOUT
THE MONEY, MICHAEL.
IT'S ABOUT NANA.
I THINK MOM SENT HER
TO A NURSING HOME--
SOME GRAY, WINDOWLESS ROOM--
AGAINST HER WILL.
- SO WHAT WAS IT LIKE
OUT THERE TODAY?
- NICE. SUNNY.
- WOW.
- SO, HOW DO YOU THINK GOB'S
GONNA MAKE THIS YACHT DISAPPEAR?
- WELL, I'LL BE WORKING HERE,
SO I GUESS I'LL NEVER KNOW.
- THE ONLY REAL WAY TO FIND OUT
HOW IT'S DONE...
IS TO SNEAK ON THE BOAT
WHILE HE DOES IT.
- BUT IF HE MAKES IT DISAPPEAR,
WON'T EVERYONE SEE ME
STANDING THERE?
- LET'S JUST SIT QUIETLY
AND CONSIDER HOW RIDICULOUS
THAT STATEMENT WAS.
ANYWAYS, IF IT WAS ME,
THAT'S WHAT I WOULD DO.
- I WANNA CHECK OUT
MOM'S FINANCIAL ACTIVITY.
CALL HER BANKS,
MAYBE RUN A HOSPITAL SEARCH.
- IT'S GONNA MEAN
A LOT OF HARD WORK,
BUT I'LL PUT SOMEBODY ON IT.
GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHERE IS GEORGE MICHAEL?
[narrator]
IN FACT, AT MAEBY'S SUGGESTION,
GEORGE MICHAEL WAS OFF TO VISIT
HIS UNCLE GOB.
- HI, UNCLE GOB.
I CAME BY TO SEE...
IF YOU NEED ANY HELP
WITH YOUR MAGIC SHOW.
- GREAT.
- I THINK IT'S SO GREAT
THAT YOU'RE DOING THIS.
- I'M PREPPING RIGHT NOW.
- HOW'D YOU GET
MY DAD'S PERMISSION?
[narrator]
SUDDENLY, GOB REMEMBERED
THE PROMISE HE HAD MADE...
TO STAY AWAY
FROM MICHAEL'S SON.
- NONE OF YOUR DAMN BUSINESS.
GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
- WHAT?
- YOU DON'T HAVE
THE MAGIC IN YOU!
YOU NEVER DID!
YOU DON'T HAVE IT HERE!
SO TAKE A GOOD LOOK.
IT'S THE LAST TIME
YOU'RE GONNA SEE THESE.
[quietly] SORRY, KID,
MORE THAN YOU'LL EVER--
- WHAT?
- BEAT IT!
[narrator]
AS GOB WAS FORCED
TO SEND AWAY SOMEONE HE LOVED-
- [quietly] YOU'LL BE MISSED.
[narrator]
GEORGE SR. WAS FORCED
TO VISIT...
SOMEONE HE HAD ONCE TRIED
TO SHOVE OUT OF A MOVING CAR.
- WELCOME.
- YOU'RE DOROTHY?
- I THOUGHT THE TWO OF US
COULD TALK, MAN-ON-MAN.
I'M AFRAID I'M SERIOUS.
I BOUGHT YOU.
REMEMBER TO LET IT STEEP
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
- OH, DEAR GOD.
- I'VE BEEN IN THIS FAMILY
FOR 16 YEARS,
AND I DON'T THINK WE'VE
EVER HAD A CONVERSATION.
- I'M NOT GONNA DISCUSS THIS.
- YOU HATE ME.
- YEAH, I DO HATE YOU.
YOU TOOK MY DAUGHTER--
MY PRECIOUS LITTLE GIRL--
AND MOVED HER AWAY,
AND NOW I'M HERE,
AND I AM AFRAID
I WILL NEVER GET HER BACK.
- AFRAID.
YOU'RE AFRAID.
FEAR HAS TURNED INTO HATE.
SO FRIGHTENED INMATE \#2
ISN'T FRIGHTENED AT ALL.
HE'S ANGRY.
HE'S A CRABBY OLD COOT,
AND HE NEEDS LOVE,
JUST LIKE EVERYONE.
[inmates go "aw"]
- GET YOUR-- [beeps]
HANDS OFF OF ME.
- SHH.
DON'T BE SCARED.
[singing]
SOMEWHERE OVER THE RAINBOW
THERE'S ANOTHER RAINBOW
[narrator]
AND ON THE BEACH,
THE SHOW WAS BEGINNING.
[crowd cheering]
[Europe's
The Final Countdown playing.]
- ANY MAGICIAN CAN MAKE
THE QUEEN OF DIAMONDS DISAPPEAR,
BUT WHAT ABOUT A WHOLE BOAT?
[cheering intensifies]
[continues]
[singing]
IT'S THE FINAL COUNTDOWN
THE FINAL COUNTDOWN
[cheering continues]
- MOM, HAVE YOU SEEN
GEORGE MICHAEL?
- WE JUST GOT HERE.
I COULDN'T FIND MY KEYS.
I CAN NEVER FIND
ANYTHING IN HERE.
- WHERE ONCE THERE WAS A YACHT,
NOW THERE IS NAUGHT!
[cheering continues]
- ALL RIGHT.
SO HOW'D YOU DO IT?
- MICHAEL, A MAGICIAN
NEVER REVEALS HIS--
I SUNK IT!
I SUNK THE YACHT!
AT LEAST I THINK I SUNK IT.
I MEAN, I BLEW IT UP,
AND I DON'T SEE IT ANYWHERE.
MY HEART WAS IN MY THROAT WHEN
THAT CURTAIN CAME DOWN AND--
[laughing]
- YOU SANK THE YACHT?
- SHH!
- YOU SUNK A $700,000 YACHT?
- $900,000 WORTH
OF INSURANCE ON IT.
AND GOT RID OF THE EVIDENCE.
HOW ABOUT A "GOOD JOB"?
[narrator]
SEEING A WINDOW
OF OPPORTUNITY, LUCILLE MADE
A STARTLING ANNOUNCEMENT.
- NANA WAS ON THAT YACHT!
- WHAT?
- YOU KILLED NANA.
- SHE'S LYING!
NANA WASN'T ON THAT YACHT.
SHE'S FINE.
SHE'S BEEN DEAD FOR SIX MONTHS.
[narrator]
LINDSAY HAD
LEARNED THIS INFORMATION--
- FOR ABOUT SIX MONTHS.
[narrator]
WHEN SHE SPOKE TO
THE FAMILY'S PERSONAL BANKER.
LATER, FEARING THAT
LINDSAY WAS ONTO HER,
LUCILLE WENT
TO THE BANK HERSELF.
- THERE MUST BE SOMEWHERE
I CAN PUT THIS MONEY
WHERE IT CAN'T BE TOUCHED.
- I SUPPOSE YOU COULD KEEP IT
IN YOUR PURSE.
- VERY FUNNY, BUT I'M
NOT CARRYING... A PURSE.
- WHERE'S THE MONEY, MOM?
I WANT THE MONEY.
- YOU CAN'T HAVE IT.
IT'S IN A TRUST FUND
FOR ANNYONG.
- ANNYONG.
- NO ONE CAN TOUCH IT BUT ME,
AND I RETAIN CONTROL OF IT
UNTIL HE'S 18.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S MORE
OFFENSIVE--
THE FACT
YOU DIDN'T TELL US...
ABOUT OUR GRANDMOTHER'S DEATH
OR THAT YOU SUNK
A $700,000 YACHT!
- STOP LECTURING ME.
I JUST LOST MY MOTHER.
- I'M SO GLAD GEORGE MICHAEL
WASN'T HERE TO SEE ANY OF THIS.
MAEBY, WHERE IS
GEORGE MICHAEL?
- UM, WELL, IF HE'S NOT HERE,
I'D JUST HAVE TO SAY
HE'S PROBABLY ON THE YACHT.
- ON THE YACHT?
[narrator]
IN FACT, GEORGE MICHAEL
HAD BOARDED THE YACHT.
BUT WHEN HE SAW THE EVIDENCE
OF GOB'S LIFESTYLE,
HE REALIZED THAT THIS PERHAPS
WAS NOT THE LIFE HE WANTED.
WHILE KITTY WENT IN SEARCH
OF RETRIBUTION...
IN THE FORM OF THE FILES
IN THE COOLER.
- GEORGE MICHAEL'S A GOOD KID.
I'M SURE HE'S AT THE OFFICE.
- RIGHT. I TOLD HIM
TO STAY AWAY FROM YOU.
AND I TOLD YOU
TO STAY AWAY FROM HIM!
- I TRIED.
I TOLD HIM TO GET OUT.
- BLUTH COMPANY.
GEORGE MICHAEL SPEAKING,
NOT KITTY.
- THANK GOD YOU'RE THERE.
- I DON'T NEED
A REAL SPRING BREAK.
I REALLY THINK I AM
MUCH BETTER OFF HERE
ALONE IN THIS OFFICE.
[narrator]
MICHAEL REALIZED
WHAT HE HAD DONE TO HIS SON,
SO HE CAME UP WITH A SOLUTION.
YOU'RE FIRED.
- REALLY?
CAN YOU FIRE PEOPLE?
- YEAH.
GO HAVE A SPRING BREAK.
- THANKS, DAD.
ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE GONNA
BE OKAY WITHOUT KITTY?
- DON'T YOU WORRY.
SHE'LL TURN UP.
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
LUPE MAKES
A STARTLING DISCOVERY.
- OH, SO THAT MAKES
ANNYONG 18.
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL FINDS HIMSELF
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE SEARCH...
FOR A MISSING KITTY.
- WELL, WE HAVE A RESTAURANT
FULL OF PEOPLE SAYING...
THAT YOU THREATENED
KITTY THE LAST TIME
SHE WAS SEEN.
- HOW DOES ANYBODY
EVEN REMEMBER THIS?
- SHE SHOWED HER KNOBS
IN A STEAKHOUSE, SIR.
- SHE--