narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL WAS MEETING
WITH THE COMPANY'S ACCOUNTANT,
IRA GILLIGAN.
- ANYWAY, I HAVE GONE OVER THIS
10 DIFFERENT WAYS,
AND YOU'RE REPORTING INCOME
ON AN ACCOUNT THAT--
YOU KNOW,
IT IS JUST FREEZING IN HERE.
- WELL, THE THERMOSTAT
IS IN MY OFFICE.
WHILE IT'S FREEZING IN HERE,
IT'S STILL HOT IN THERE.
SO PLEASE CONTINUE.
- THERE'S BASICALLY NO MONEY
WHERE IT SHOULD BE.
I THINK I'M CATCHING A COLD.
- YOU'RE NOT
CATCHING A COLD.
- I KNOW MY BODY.
- SO THERE'S NO MONEY IN THE
ACCOUNT?
- I'M SORRY.
THIS IS LIKE
THE BAYOU IN HERE.
- I TRIED TO TELL YOU THAT.
- WELL I GUESS I JUST HAD
TO FIND OUT FOR MYSELF.
ANYWAY, THIS ISN'T THE FIRST
DISCREPANCY
WITH YOUR FATHER'S BOOKS.
AND WITH THIS COURT CASE COMING
UP, I JUST HAVE TO WARN YOU...
IF THEY ASK ME TO TESTIFY,
I AM NOT GONNA LIE.
- NO ONE'S ASKING YOU
TO LIE.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
YOU'RE ASKING GILLIGAN
NOT TO LIE?
PLEASE CALL ME IRA.
I DON'T LIKE GILLIGAN.
- WHO DOESN'T LIKE GILLIGAN?
IS IT COLD IN HERE?
- SO, LISTEN. YOU HAVE BEEN
MARRIED TWO WEEKS NOW.
IT SEEMS TO BE STICKING.
AND LET'S PRETEND
IT'S A GOOD THING.
I GUESS THIS MAKES ME
YOUR BEST MAN,
AND I WOULD LIKE TO THROW YOU
A BACHELOR PARTY.
- YEAH, I DON'T THINK
SHE'D GO FOR THAT.
BESIDES, I TALKED TO DAD.
HE SAID IT WAS STUPID TO GET
MARRIED IN THE FIRST PLACE.
AND HE'S RIGHT. HE'S RIGHT.
I'VE GOTTA GET RID OF HER.
- YOU KNOW, I--I SAID
TWO WEEKS AGO
THAT I THOUGHT
IT WAS A STUPID IDEA.
SUDDENLY DAD SAYS IT
AND IT'S GOOD ADVICE?
YOU KNOW YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO
EVERYTHING DAD SAYS.
- I DON'T DO EVERYTHING DAD
SAYS.
HE JUST HAPPENS TO BE RIGHT
ABOUT THIS.
YOU CAN HELP ME
GET RID OF HER THOUGH.
MOM'S HAVING A COCKTAIL PARTY.
SHE'LL BE THERE.
MAYBE YOU CAN
TRY TO BREAK US UP.
- I CAN'T DO THAT.
- WHY NOT? YOU DID IT
WITH ME AND MARTA.
YOU HAD NO PROBLEM
WITH THAT, GUY.
YOU KNOW WHAT? LIE TO HER.
TELL HER THAT I'M INSENSITIVE
AND UNRELIABLE.
- MAYBE SOMETHING ABOUT HOW YOU
CAN NEVER CONFRONT PEOPLE.
AND YOU NEED
SOMEONE TO CLEAN UP YOUR MESSES.
- SEE, THAT'S GREAT.
AND THAT'S JUST
OFF THE TOP OF YOUR HEAD.
- MICHAEL, GOB. I WAS JUST
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
GOOD LORD.
IT IS SWELTERING IN HERE.
AS YOU MAY
OR MAY NOT KNOW,
LINDSAY AND I HAVE HIT
A BIT OF A ROUGH PATCH.
- REALLY?
WHEN DID THAT START?
- WELL, I DON'T WANT
TO BLAME IT ALL ON 9/11,
BUT IT CERTAINLY
DIDN'T HELP.
BUT ANYWAY, I NEED YOUR HELP.
IF YOU COULD POSSIBLY--
COULD WE GO BACK
TO YOUR OFFICE, PLEASE?
I JUST WANT TO BE
A FAMILY AGAIN.
I GUESS WHAT I'M SAYING IS
I WANT TO REUNITE THE BAND.
- OH, NO.
narrator:
"OH, NO" WAS RIGHT.
IN THE MID '90S, TOBIAS FORMED
A FOLK MUSIC GROUP
WITH LINDSAY AND MAEBY,
CALLED DR. FUNKE'S 100% NATURAL
GOOD-TIME FAMILY-BAND SOLUTION.
THE GROUP WAS UNDERWRITTEN BY
THE NATURAL LIFE FOOD COMPANY,
A DIVISION OF CHEM GROW,
AN ALLYN-CRANE ACQUISITION,
AND PART OF THE SQUIMM GROUP.
THEIR MOTTO WAS SIMPLE.
"WE KEEP YOU ALIVE."
- [singing] KIND OF LIFE THAT IS
EVEN JUST A LITTLE BIT
BETTER WITH A ZANOTAB
- ZANOTAB MAY CAUSE DRY MOUTH,
HAIR LOSS,
AN OVERLY ALERT FEELING,
AND IN SOME CASES MAY
DIMINISH YOUR SEX DRIVE.
- [singing] ZANOTAB
- WELL, THERE'S A WELLNESS
CONVENTION IN TOWN,
AND I THOUGHT MAYBE YOU COULD
TALK LINDSAY
INTO JOINING ME UP ONSTAGE.
- YEAH.
WHY DON'T YOU ASK HER?
- OH, I WOULD, BUT SHE JUST
DOESN'T TAKE ME SERIOUSLY.
narrator: AND MICHAEL TRIED TO
FIND THE MONEY
THE ACCOUNTANT SAID WAS MISSING.
- I DON'T KNOW.
I PROBABLY STOLE IT.
I MEAN, IF HE SAYS
IT'S MISSING, IT IS.
UNLESS HE STOLE IT.
HEY, MAYBE HE STOLE IT.
- HE'S THE ONE
THAT SAID IT'S MISSING.
- YEAH, I PROBABLY STOLE IT.
- WELL, WE NEED TO FIND IT
BEFORE IRA IS ASKED
TO TESTIFY.
- I THOUGHT WE WERE TALKING
ABOUT GILLIGAN. WHO'S IRA?
- IRA GILLIGAN.
IRA'S HIS FIRST NAME.
HE ACTUALLY HATES
TO BE CALLED GILLIGAN.
- WELL,
HE NEVER TOLD ME THAT.
GILLIGAN HAS PROMISED ME
THAT ALL THIS MONEY WILL BE
SAVED IN I.R.A.S.
- IT'S IRA, SIR.
- OH, I'M SORRY, GILLIGAN.
WILL BE SAVED IN "IRAS."
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS,
GILLIGAN?
- IT'S IRA, SIR.
PLEASE CALL ME--
- GILLIGAN!
MICHAEL, IF HE TESTIFIES,
I AM SCREWED.
HERE'S WHAT YOU DO.
YOU TAKE HIM OUT
FOR SOME FISHING OR SOMETHING.
- WHY WOULD I TAKE HIM FISHING?
- FUN. GUY FUN.
LET'S GET HIM ON OUR SIDE.
- NO. LOOK.
I'M NOT TAKING HIM FISHING.
- OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU HATED FISHING.
- NO, I DIDN'T.
- NO, I'LL GET GOB.
YEAH. HE LIKED IT.
- HANG ON A SECOND.
- HE'S THE ONE WHO'S FUN.
- I LIKED FISHING.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I'M FUN.
IT'S JUST THAT--
LISTEN.
THE WAY TO FIX THIS IRA THING IS
NOT TO BUY HIM OFF.
ALL RIGHT?
IT'S TO FIND OUT
WHERE THE MONEY WENT.
- YOU'RE NO FUN.
- YEAH.
I'M PLENTY FUN.
narrator: THAT NIGHT THE FAMILY
GATHERED AT LUCILLE'S...
TO WELCOME GOB'S WIFE.
- I HAVE ALWAYS WANTED
A DAUGHTER.
- [gasps]
- AND A BLONDE.
WHAT FUN.
- WHERE DID ANNYONG
GET THAT JUICE BOX?
- ANNOYONG.
- THOSE ARE FOR HIS SOCCER TEAM.
NO SUGAR FOR YOU.
YOU JUST GET MORE AWFUL.
- HEY, ADOPTED BROTHER.
DO YOU THINK I COULD HAVE A HIT
OF THAT JUICE BOX? THAT--
[sucking air]
narrator: AND MICHAEL TRIED TO
CONVINCE LINDSAY TO REJOIN...
DR. FUNKE'S 100% NATURAL
GOOD TIME FAMILY BAND SOLUTION.
- DR. FUNKE'S 100% NATURAL
GOOD TIME FAMILY BAND SOLUTION
WAS A NIGHTMARE FOR ME.
- HMM.
WELL, HE SAID IT WAS
THE MOST FUN YOUR FAMILY'S
EVER HAD.
- YEAH, WELL, I WAS WACKED ON
ZANOTAB THE ENTIRE TIME.
- I THOUGHT ZANOTAB
WAS SUPPOSED TO MAKE
EVERYTHING A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
- FOR 15 MINUTES.
THEN IT BURNS WHEN YOU PEE,
AND YOUR MARRIAGE GOES TO HELL.
IT IS NOT A GOOD SUPPLEMENT.
BESIDES, MAEBY'S NOT GONNA WANT
TO DO IT.
- I WANNA DO IT!
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THOSE WERE
OUR BEST TIMES EVER.
- THIS PARTY JUST KEEPS
GETTIN' BETTER.
- SO, UH-- YOU KNOW,
IF YOU WANT ME ON WOOD BLOCK,
I CAN KEEP PERFECT TIME.
SOME CALL ME
THE HUMAN METRONOME.
YOU NOTICE HOW I'M ALWAYS ON
TIME?
I'M NEVER LATE FOR THINGS.
- YEAH, BUT I THINK PUNCTUALITY
IS SLIGHTLY DIFFERENT FROM
RHYTHM.
- NO, IT'S NOT.
NO, IT'S THE EXACT SAME THING.
IT'S KNOWING
HOW LONG THINGS TAKE.
- LOOK. I'M JUST DOING THIS
BECAUSE IF MY PARENTS SPLIT UP,
IT'S A LOT MORE WORK FOR ME.
I KNOW.
THEY SPLIT UP ONCE IN BOSTON.
WHEN THEY GET ALONG,
I GET TONS MORE ALONE TIME.
WHEN THEY DON'T,
GUESS WHO THEY START SPENDING
ALL THEIR TIME WITH.
ME.
- WE'VE BEEN TALKING HERE FOR
28 SECONDS. JUST SO YOU KNOW.
- EXCUSE ME.
DR. "FUNKY?"
- AH, FUNKE
- OF DR. FUNKE'S 100% NATURAL
GOOD TIME FAMILY BAND SOLUTION?
- YES!
- OH, MY--
I SAW YOU IN '96.
- OH!
- YOU SANG A SONG ABOUT
A SUPPLEMENT CALLED TEAMOCIL?
- TEAMOCIL.
- I MEAN,
YOU JUST NAILED ME!
IT WAS LIKE YOU KNEW
EVERY SIDE EFFECT I WAS
GOING THROUGH AT THAT TIME.
- [singing] THERE'S NO "I" IN
TEAMOCIL
AT LEAST NOT WHERE
YOU'D THINK
- SADLY, TEAMOCIL HAS BEEN
DISCONTINUED.
- OH.
- THE SENSE OF WELLNESS
IT CREATED IN RELATIONSHIPS...
WAS MERELY THE FIRST SIGN OF
COMPLETE PITUITARY SHUTDOWN.
- EXCUSE ME? ARE YOU, UH--
HI. I'M MICHAEL.
- HI.
- I'M GOB'S BROTHER.
- YES. HE TOLD ME
ALL ABOUT YOU.
YOU HAVE A TERRIFIC VOICE.
- I SMELL OLIVES!
narrator: AND MICHAEL,
AS PER GOB'S REQUEST,
TRIED TO CONVINCE HIS WIFE
THAT GOB WAS UNRELIABLE.
- SO, GOB IS LATE. BUT I GUESS
THAT'S WHO YOU MARRIED.
HE'S PROBABLY OUT TRYING TO DO
SOMETHING VERY IMPORTANT.
- ARE YOU HITTING ON ME?
GOB SAID THAT WOULD HAPPEN.
[door opens,
closes]
- HEY, GOB.
IT'S A GOOD THING YOU'RE NOT
STAYING MARRIED TO THIS GIRL.
YOU'VE GOT HER HATING ME--
AT LEAST YOUR VERSION OF ME,
WHICH IS ACTUALLY YOU.
- WELL, I TALKED TO DAD,
AND HE THINKS THAT I SHOULD
STAY IN IT.
- STAY IN THE MARRIAGE?
OH, COME ON,
YOU'RE NOT LETTING DAD
LEAD YOU AROUND BY THE NOSE
AGAIN, ARE YOU?
- THINK ABOUT IT.
I'VE GOT THE MARRIAGE AND NONE
OF THE GOOD PARTS.
IT'S LIKE, SO FAR IT'S BEEN
ALL CHAIN AND NO BALL.
- SURE.
- SO, WE'LL HAVE A CEREMONY
AND A BACHELOR PARTY.
- A BACHELOR PARTY?
YOU WANT ONE NOW?
COME ON.
YOU'RE NOT GIVING YOUR BEST MAN
A WHOLE LOT OF PREP TIME.
- DAD CAN HANDLE IT.
- DAD?
- YEAH. YOU KNOW.
HE'S A FUN GUY, AND...
I'M MAKING HIM MY BEST MAN.
- YOU'RE MAKING DAD
YOUR BEST MAN. THAT'S GREAT.
I GUESS
BEING YOUR BROTHER...
AND SOLVING ALL YOUR PROBLEMS
FOR YOU
DOESN'T QUALIFY ME
AS YOUR BEST MAN.
- HEY.
IF HE WANTS TO SUPPORT ME,
I'M NOT GONNA TELL HIM
TO GO TO HELL.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'RE STILL--
- WHAT?
INVITED?
- NO, I WAS GONNA SAY
YOU'RE STILL THE GUY I WANT
SOLVING MY PROBLEMS, BUT, YEAH--
LET ME TALK TO DAD
ABOUT THAT INVITE SITUATION.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY,
GOB VISITED HIS FATHER...
TO PREPARE
FOR HIS BACHELOR PARTY.
- YOU KNOW, I REALLY THINK THAT
YOU'RE GONNA LIKE THIS WOMAN.
- WELL, SHE'S COSTING ME ENOUGH,
BUT SHE'S--OH, SHE'S
A HELL OF A STRIPPER.
- NO, I MEAN MY WIFE.
- OH.
WELL, I--I DOUBT THAT
VERY MUCH.
- WELL, I CAN TELL YOU THAT
MICHAEL WAS PRETTY UPSET
THAT YOU WANTED TO BE BEST MAN.
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT MICHAEL.
- YEAH, MY BACHELOR PARTY'S
ABOUT HAVING FUN, RIGHT?
- NO, NO. YOUR BACHELOR PARTY'S
ABOUT CONVINCING GILLIGAN
THAT HE'S KILLED A STRIPPER,
GETTING HIM OUT OF TOWN
SO HE CAN'T TESTIFY...
AND MAKING SURE THAT PEOPLE
THINK THAT HE TOOK THE MONEY.
- IT IS?
- YEAH.
THIS ACCOUNTANT CAN DO US
A LOT OF DAMAGE.
I WANT HIM NEUTRALIZED.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
THAT'S WHY I WANT YOU TO USE
THIS STRIPPER--
A NARCOLEPTIC,
BELIEVE IT OR NOT.
A FRIEND OF MINE
AT THE YACHT CLUB,
HE USED HER
FOR HIS BACHELOR PARTY.
- WE WANTED YOU
TO HAVE THE FIRST PIECE!
[snoring]
[men laughing]
YOU PUT HER IN A DARKENED SPACE,
SHE'S OUT.
YOU GET HIM DRUNK.
HE PASSES OUT.
THEN YOU COVER THE FLOOR
WITH CORN SYRUP,
MIXED
WITH A LITTLE RED DYE.
HE COMES TO.
"EEE! BLOOD! AAAH!"
HE FREAKS OUT.
- OKAY.
BUT HOW DO YOU KNOW
THAT HE'S GONNA LEAVE
THE COUNTRY?
- THAT'S WHY I GOT YOU
THOSE HONEYMOON TICKETS.
YOU NEVER THANKED ME FOR THOSE.
- [stammering] I'M SORRY.
I MEANT TO. I WAS GONNA--
- YOU JUST HAVE TO CONVINCE HIM
THAT THIS HAPPENED.
- THAT HE KILLED A STRIPPER?
- CAN YOU DO THIS?
CAN I TRUST YOU?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GO ALL MICHAEL
ON ME, ARE YA?
- NOBODY'S TURNING
ALL MICHAEL ON YOU.
BUT WHEN YOU GET OUT, THEN WE'RE
GONNA HAVE A REAL PARTY.
RIGHT, DAD?
- ARE YOU KIDDING?
WHEN I GET OUT OF HERE,
YOU'RE GONNA THROW ME THE
BIGGEST PARTY THIS TOWN'S EVER
SEEN, ALL RIGHT?
narrator:
BACK AT THE MODEL HOME--
- [singing] ALL JUST A LITTLE
BIT BETTER WITH EUPHORAZINE
- ZANOTAB!
- STOP!
IT IS NOT ZANOTAB.
- WELL, MAYBE IF I WAS
ALLOWED TO HAVE A ZANOTAB,
I'D REMEMBER IT'S EUPHORAZINE.
- NO. WE ARE NOT GOING TO DO
THAT AGAIN.
THIS FAMILY
IS NOT ABOUT TO START USING.
WE ARE PUSHERS,
NOT TAKERS.
OKAY. ONCE MORE,
FROM THE BRIDGE.
[scoffs]
- [singing] BECAUSE I HAVE A
BROTHER AND A MOTHER AND A LOVER
AND A WIFE AND A DAUGHTER
- WHAT IS THAT NOISE?
WE DON'T NEED
THE WOOD BLOCK.
- NO, I JUST THOUGHT I WOULD
JOIN IN ON THE FUN.
I MEAN, YOU GUYS ARE ALWAYS
TALKING ABOUT,
YOU KNOW,
FAMILY AND LOVING AND...
HAVING GOOD TIMES
IN THE CIRCLE--
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
THIS ISN'T WORKING.
MAYBE I'M JUST GONNA GO OFF
AND REHEARSE WITH MAEBY ALONE.
- OH, FINE.
THEN I'LL REHEARSE
WITH MAEBY AFTER DINNER.
- NO! THIS IS WHOLESOME,
FAMILY FUN, OKAY?
LET'S TAKE IT FROM LOOSE STOOL!
ONE, TWO AND A--
- WHAT IS THAT IN YOUR MOUTH?
IS THAT A EUPHORAZINE?
LINDSAY, SPIT IT OUT!
THAT'S NOT REAL HAPPINESS!
- WELL, IT'S BETTER
THAN WHAT WE'VE GOT NOW.
- LINDSAY, SPIT IT OUT!
narrator:
AND MICHAEL ARRIVED HOME,
DETERMINED TO PROVE
THAT HE WAS, IN FACT, FUN.
- I JUST BOOKED US
A LITTLE FISHING TRIP.
- BUT WHY?
WHAT DID I DO?
- HMM? NO, NO.
THIS IS A FUN THING!
OKAY? SOMETHING I'VE ALWAYS
WANTED TO DO WITH YOU.
EVERYBODY'S ALWAYS HAVING FUN
AROUND HERE. WHY CAN'T WE?
- [Lindsay, muffled]
ALREADY DOWN!
GET YOUR FINGER
OUT OF MY THROAT! IT'S DOWN!
- ANYWAY, I THOUGHT
YOU HATED FISHING.
- NO, IT'S FUN.
I LIKE FUN.
I JUST HATED DOING IT
WITH MY DAD.
THIS IS GONNA BE
YOU AND ME. OKAY?
WE GET TO STAY AT A HOTEL,
GET UP AT 4:00 A.M.,
SLAP ON
THE OLD SEASICK PATCH.
WE'RE GONNA GET OUT THERE
ON THE CHOPPY OCEAN.
WE'RE GONNA
CATCH OURSELVES A LITTLE LUNCH.
- OH, WE GET TO EAT IT?
- AFTER WE GUT IT.
- YES.
narrator: WHILE THE BLUTH BOYS
CONTEMPLATED HAVING FUN,
LUCILLE HAD A REQUEST
FOR GOB'S BACHELOR PARTY.
- WHY DO I HAVE TO
BRING HIM?
- BECAUSE BUSTER'S YOUR BROTHER,
AND I'M NOT GONNA LEAVE HIM
HOME ALONE WITH ALL THIS
J-U-I-C-E AROUND.
- I CAN SPELL, MOM.
YOU SPELLED "JUICE."
- OH, YOU'RE SO BRILLIANT.
LET'S SEE YOU FIND IT.
BESIDES, I'M GOING TO ANNYONG'S
SOCCER AWARD CEREMONY--
- ANNYONG.
- AND I DON'T NEED THE OTHER
SOCCER MOMS
KNOWING HOW OLD
MY FIRST BATCH OF KIDS ARE.
- YEAH, I THINK THEY'RE GONNA
KNOW THAT ANNYONG'S--
- ANNYONG.
- WOULD SOMEBODY PLEASE TELL
THIS INSUFFERABLE CHILD TO--
GOD!
narrator: AND SO,
AS MICHAEL AND HIS SON...
CHECKED INTO THE HOTEL,
HIS BROTHERS ARRIVED.
- WHAT ARE YOU GUYS DOING HERE?
- OH, WE'RE HAVING
GOB'S BACHELOR PARTY.
YOU'RE NOT GOING?
Even dad's coming-- [giggles]
VIA SATELLITE.
- UH, NO. I'M GONNA
GO FISHING WITH MY SON HERE.
WE'RE GONNA GO HAVE SOME FUN.
REAL FUN. OKAY?
NOT EVERYTHING IS STRIPPERS
AND BOOZE AND BUCKETS OF BLOOD.
WHY DO YOU GUYS
HAVE BUCKETS OF BLOOD?
- IT'S NOT REAL BLOOD.
IT'S CORN SYRUP AND RED DYE.
- JUICE.
- WE HAVE UNLIMITED JUICE?
[chuckles] THIS PARTY IS GONNA
BE OFF THE HOOK.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
AT THE WELLNESS CONVENTION
IN THE VERY SAME HOTEL,
DR. FUNKE'S 100% NATURAL GOOD
TIME FAMILY-BAND SOLUTION
WAS PREPARING FOR THEIR SHOW.
- HERE ARE THE NEW
EUPHORAZINE SIDE EFFECTS.
- AH, THE SOLO.
THAT IS FOR MY LOVELY
AND TALENTED DAUGHTER.
- "DELAYED IRRITABILITY?"
WHAT DO THEY MEAN
BY DELAYED?
- IT MEANS IT COMES LATER!
THIS IS RIDICULOUS!
WHY DO WE
EVEN HAVE TO DO THIS?
- WE ARE DOING THIS TO KEEP OUR
FAMILY TOGETHER.
- NO, I'M SERIOUS.
LOOK AT US.
WE'RE DRESSED LIKE
WE'RE IN THE '60S.
IT'S THE 21ST CENTURY. WE SHOULD
BE DRESSING LIKE IT'S THE '80S.
- LINDSAY--
- I'M TIRED OF TRYING TO FIND
HAPPINESS
THROUGH LIES
AND SELF-MEDICATING.
IF YOU NEED ME,
I'LL BE AT THE BAR.
- WELL, FINE, LINDSAY.
THAT'S FINE.
MAEBY AND I'LL JUST DO--
- YEAH. I'M OUT TOO.
- YOU THINK YOU CAN HANDLE IT
ALONE?
'CAUSE IF YOU DON'T
PERFORM, WE DON'T VALIDATE.
narrator: BACK IN MICHAEL'S
HOTEL ROOM,
THE GUYS WERE SETTLING DOWN
FOR THE NIGHT,
SO AS TO BE READY FOR THEIR
4:00 A.M. WAKE-UP CALL.
- IT SURE SOUNDS LIKE THEY'RE
HAVING FUN
OUT THERE BY THE POOL.
- OH, THEY THINK THEY'RE HAVING
FUN, SON,
BUT IT'S NOT LASTING FUN.
IT IS FLEETING FUN,
LIKE A BACHELOR PARTY.
WHAT WE GOT HERE
IS LASTING FUN.
OKAY?
YOU THINK ABOUT THAT.
GOOD NIGHT, SON.
- GOOD NIGHT, DAD.
- MARCO!
- POLO!
- HEY, DAD?
- DAD, ARE YOU STILL AWAKE?
- STILL AWAKE.
- IT'S JUST, UM--
I MEAN, THIS IS REALLY FUN
AND EVERYTHING--
- THIS ISN'T EVEN THE FUN PART.
TOMORROW--
- YEAH.
THE PROBLEM I'M HAVING
IS, UH--
I HAVE A PRETTY FINELY TUNED
INTERNAL CLOCK--
- MM-HMM.
WHICH IS WHY I'M ACTUALLY SUCH A
GOOD NATURAL PERCUSSIONIST.
AND, UM--
I'M JUST WORRIED THAT I'M NOT
GONNA BE ABLE TO FALL ASLEEP...
FOR ANOTHER TWO HOURS
AND 45 MINUTES.
SO, I WAS THINKING
MAYBE I WOULD GO DOWN
AND CHECK OUT MAEBY'S BAND,
AND YOU COULD GO SEE
IF GOB'S BACHELOR PARTY
HAS STARTED.
- SHH, SHH, SHH.
I'M RIGHT WHERE I WANT TO BE.
GOB HAD HIS CHANCE
TO HAVE ME THERE,
BUT IF YOU'RE SURE
THAT YOU CAN'T SLEEP.
- WELL, IT'S JUST--I DON'T KNOW
WHEN I'M GONNA GET ANOTHER
CHANCE LIKE THIS,
YOU KNOW, TO BE THERE FOR
FAMILY.
- RIGHT.
- I'D HATE TO MISS IT,
BECAUSE I WAS TOO PROUD.
- RIGHT.
WAIT A MINUTE.
"TOO PROUD?"
WHAT DOES THIS HAVE TO DO
WITH "TOO PROUD?"
- ACTUALLY, THAT PART
WAS KINDA JUST FOR YOU.
I WAS JUST WORRIED THE WHOLE
THING WASN'T GONNA LAND
UNLESS I INCLUDED THE PRIDE
PART.
narrator: UPSTAIRS, GOB WAS
PREPARING
TO SET UP THE ACCOUNTANT,
UNDER HIS FATHER'S
HELPFUL GAZE.
- WHO CALLED THE COPS?
narrator: AND WITH THE AID
OF SOME HELPFUL GAYS.
- YOU TOLD ME TO HIRE PEOPLE
TO LOOK LIKE MY FRIENDS.
THEY'RE HOT COPS.
THEY'RE ENTERTAINERS.
ALTHOUGH I SPECIFICALLY
ASKED THEM
NOT TO COME
DRESSED AS COPS.
YOU BETTER CHANGE NOW.
HE'S GONNA BE HERE SOON.
BUTCH, GUYS. I WANT IT BUTCH.
- HEY, UH,
YOU GOT THE BLOOD. RIGHT?
- YEAH, I GOT TWO BUCKETS FULL
RIGHT--
HEY! WHAT THE HELL
HAPPENED TO THE BLOOD?
[giggling]
- HEY, BROTHER.
- WHOA!
SOMEBODY PUT ON HIS LIPSTICK IN
THE CAR.
- I LOVE JUICE!
- THIS NEXT NUMBER
IS THE ONLY BALLAD
THAT THE SOLUTION
EVER ATTEMPTED.
AND I MUST SAY
I FEEL A BIT LIKE A MARY...
WITHOUT A PETER AND A PAUL,
BUT I SUPPOSE IT'S WORTH A SHOT.
[singing] THERE'S NO "I" IN
TEAMOCIL
AT LEAST NOT WHERE
YOU'D THINK
[strumming]
SO TOGETHER
LET'S MAKE A CHOICE
- AND FOR ONCE
WE'LL BE IN SYNC
- TEAMOCI-IL
- I NEVER THOUGHT
I KNEW YOU WELL
- TEAMOCI-I-IL
- NOW I THINK
WE REALLY GEL
[harmonizing]
TEAMOCIL
- "TEAMOCIL IS
NO LONGER AVAILABLE.
PLEASE TRY EITHER
GROUPHUG,
BONDAT OR CONSULT
YOUR OWN WELLNESS GUIDE."
- TEAMOCIL!
[weak clapping]
- YOU'RE OUT OF THE BAND.
narrator: AND, BACK
AT THE BACHELOR PARTY...
GILLIGAN HAD ARRIVED,
AND THE CON WAS IN FULL SWING.
- IT'S IRA,
AND I'M FINE.
- COME ON!
HAVE A DRINK!
THERE'S SOME
STUFF COMING UP
YOU MIGHT NOT BE ABLE
TO HANDLE SOBER.
- SPEAKING OF WHICH,
WHERE'S BUSTER?
narrator: IN FACT, BUSTER HAD
FINISHED THE JUICE...
AND WAS DESPERATELY LOOKING
FOR HIS NEXT SUGAR FIX--
- [growls]
WHEN HE DISCOVERED THE CAKE
IN THE NEXT ROOM.
UNFORTUNATELY, HE WAS UNAWARE
OF THE NARCOLEPTIC STRIPPER
CONFINED WITHIN IT.
[screams]
[snores]
- YEAH, I BETTER GO IN THE
BACK ROOM
AND HAVE A LOOK
FOR HIM.
- IRA, HAVE A DRINK!
- I'M NOT THIRSTY.
I WANT SOME FOOD.
- OOH.
[snoring]
OKAY. KEEP IT TOGETHER.
DON'T GO ALL MICHAEL HERE.
- KNOCK, KNOCK!
WHERE'S THE MARRIED BACHELOR?
- MICHAEL,
I THOUGHT YOU WEREN'T COMING.
I THOUGHT HE WASN'T COMING!
- WELL, I WASN'T GOING TO,
BUT HE'S MY BROTHER,
AND I'M HERE TO SUPPORT HIM,
LIKE ALL THESE, UH,
HOT MEN AND IRA.
- WELL, YOU'RE NOT
GONNA STAY.
I MEAN,
THIS ISN'T YOUR KIND OF SCENE.
DAD, PLEASE, STAY OUT OF IT,
ALL RIGHT?
I'M HERE FOR GOB.
NOW, WHERE ARE THE STRIPPERS?
- WELL, I--
- MMM! YOU GOT A LITTLE
BACK ROOM GOING, HUH?
HUH? HUH?
- WELL--
- JUST RELAX.
I'M AS FUN AS ANYBODY.
I CAN HANDLE
A BACK ROOM.
I'M CALLING THE COPS.
- NO!
- WE'RE CHANGING AGAIN, GUYS!
- NO. NO COPS.
- WELL, WHAT IS THIS?
- SHE DIED.
SHE'S DEAD.
IT WAS GILLIGAN!
- WHAT?
- GILLIGAN KILLED
THE SKIPPER--STRIPPER.
- I DIDN'T KILL
ANY STRIPPER.
- YOU'RE DRUNK.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER.
- YOU'RE PULLING THE RIP CORD!
ARE YOU NUTS?
- IRA, TAKE MY HONEYMOON
TICKETS.
GET OUT OF THE COUNTRY.
SAVE YOURSELF.
- I'M NOT DRUNK. BIX MADE ME
THE DESIGNATED DRIVER.
- BIX!
narrator:
JUST THEN, THE STRIPPER WOKE UP,
SAW BUSTER WITH WHAT APPEARED
TO BE BLOOD AROUND HIS MOUTH,
AND THOUGHT SHE HAD KILLED HIM
FOR GROPING HER.
- NOT AGAIN.
- YOU WERE SETTING ME UP.
YOU'RE TRYING TO GET ME
TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY.
WELL, THE HELL WITH YOU, SIR.
BIX, WE'RE LEAVING.
I'M TESTIFYING.
- YOU WERE TRYING
TO SET IRA UP?
- OH, GOB, GOB.
COME ON. IS THIS TRUE?
- OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
IT WASN'T YOUR IDEA, GOB.
IT WAS YOUR IDEA.
WASN'T IT, DAD?
- IT WA--
- HUH?
- EVEN IF IT WAS MY IDEA,
WHICH IT WASN'T,
GOB SCREWED IT UP,
WHICH HE DID AND ALWAYS DOES.
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO TAKE THAT.
- WHAT THE HELL
AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
- HERE.
- OH, NO. NO, NO.
DON'T YOU DARE, MISTER.
- DO IT. DO IT.
- HEY, GOB! I AM YOUR BEST MAN.
I AM YOUR FATH--
- [sighs]
WHAT DOES IT MATTER?
I SCREWED IT UP ANYWAY.
A COMPLETE FAILURE.
CAN'T EVEN FAKE THE DEATH
OF A STRIPPER.
- OH, COME ON.
THAT'S NOT A BAD THING.
IT DOESN'T MAKE YOU A FAILURE.
DAD'S THE FAILURE.
- REALLY?
WHEN HE WAS MY AGE, HE RAN
AN ENTIRE COMPANY, HAD KIDS.
- THE COMPANY WAS CORRUPT.
LOOK WHAT HE'S TRYING
TO DO TO US.
I'LL TELL YOU
SOMETHING ELSE.
YOU MIGHT NOT BE A FATHER,
YOU KNOW, GOB,
BUT YOU ARE MY BROTHER.
- I MIGHT BE A FATHER.
- WHY DON'T YOU START TRUSTING
YOURSELF. OKAY? NOT DAD.
YOU'RE A MUCH BETTER MAN
THAN HE IS.
- YOU'RE A BETTER MAN
THAN BOTH OF US.
- WELL.
- YOU'RE THE BEST MAN.
YOU'RE MY BEST MAN.
NOT IF I HAVE
AN ACTUAL CEREMONY,
'CAUSE DAD WOULD KILL ME, BUT--
WHAT DO YOU SAY, HERMANO?
HELP ME CLEAN UP
THIS MESS?
- WHAT THE HELL.
- GOB, I WANT OUT.
- I'M IN LOVE WITH YOUR BROTHER.
- WHAT?
YOU DID IT AGAIN,
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
- NO, NO!
- IN-LAW. TOBIAS.
SORRY. I SHOULD HAVE
FINISHED THAT THOUGHT.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
- OH, MY GOD.
I KILLED MICHAEL.
- YEAH, BUT ON THE PLUS SIDE,
YOU GOT PUNCHED IN THE FACE.
- HEY, BROTHER.
HEY, BROTHER.
narrator: MICHAEL SOLVES THE
MYSTERY OF THE MISSING MONEY.
- IRA WAS SIGNATORY
TO ALL THESE ACCOUNTS?
[beeps]
GET ME IRA GILLIGAN.
narrator: AND GILLIGAN...
FULFILLS HIS DESTINY.
[cell phone ringing]
- LET IT RING.