narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL WAS PREPARING
FOR A MEETING
WITH THE BLUTH COMPANY BOARD
TO DECIDE WHAT TO DO WITH
SOME RECENTLY UNFROZEN FUNDS.
- WOW. EXCITING, HUH?
FINALLY GETTING SOME MONEY.
- WHAT DO YOU WANT, LINDSAY?
- I'D LIKE SOME OF THAT MONEY.
- WELL, THIS MONEY IS FOR LAND.
OKAY? WE'RE NOT GONNA BURN
THROUGH IT
LIKE DAD DID
WHEN HE WAS IN CHARGE
WITH HIS BAD INVESTMENTS,
AND HIS CORRUPT DEALINGS--
MOTHER'S NECK.
- NO, THAT WAS
A GOOD INVESTMENT.
- IT IS EASIER TO LOOK
AT NOW, ISN'T IT?
- WHAT IF I TOLD YOU THAT
THE MONEY WAS FOR SOMETHING
REALLY WORTHWHILE?
- LIKE WHAT?
- I WANT TO HAVE AN AFFAIR.
NOW I'M NOT SURE WITH
WHO YET,
BUT I'LL NEED
LINGERIE, WAXINGS--
THESE ARE SOME
REAL COSTS, MICHAEL.
- I TAKE IT THINGS AREN'T
GETTING BETTER WITH TOBIAS.
- WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
narrator: THINGS HADN'T BEEN
GETTING BETTER
WITH MICHAEL'S SISTER
AND HER HUSBAND
EVEN AFTER SHE CAME UP WITH
A PLAN TO GET HIS ATTENTION.
[disco playing]
- OH, MY GOD.
LISTEN TO THE RADIO.
I HAVEN'T HEARD THIS SONG
SINCE WE FIRST STARTED DATING.
- [singing] BAD GIRLS
TALKIN' 'BOUT THE SAD GIRLS
- I JUST FEEL LIKE
USING MY BODY.
- WELL, LINDSAY, COULD YOU
USE IT OVER THERE?
I'M TRYING TO GROW.
- YEAH. IT'S CLEAR
THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
WE HAD SEX ONCE IN THE LAST
YEAR, AND HE JUST LAID THERE.
- ALL RIGHT. LOOK,
THIS MONEY IS FOR LAND.
I'M NOT GONNA GIVE YOU
MONEY TO HAVE AN AFFAIR.
WHY DON'T YOU PICK
SOMETHING ELSE
TO BOOST UP
YOUR SELF-WORTH?
HOW ABOUT, UH, CHARITY?
WHY DON'T YOU GET BACK
TO YOUR ROOTS?
- WELL, IT HAS BEEN A WHILE.
[inhales sharply]
ALL RIGHT!
I'M GONNA GO DO THAT
RIGHT NOW.
- YOU'RE GONNA GO GET
YOUR HAIR DONE, AREN'T YOU?
- WELL, IF I'M GONNA
HAVE AN AFFAIR--
[phone ringing]
narrator: MICHAEL GOT
A MESSAGE HE INTENDED TO IGNORE.
UNTIL HE READ THE NEXT LINE.
- A MATTER OF LAND, MOM?
- OH, THAT'S FUNNY.
I MEANT "A MATTER
OF L AND D," LIFE AND DEATH.
- WHAT IS THE MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH?
- BUSTER'S JAW CLICKS
WHEN HE EATS.
I THINK IT'S WHAT'S
DRIVING HIS FRIENDS AWAY.
I SENT HIM TO CANADA
FOR AN OPERATION.
SO I'LL NEED SOME OF THAT
NEW MONEY THAT JUST CAME IN.
- YOU KNOW, MOM,
IF YOU WANT AN OPERATION
THAT'S REALLY GONNA HELP HIM,
YOU OUGHT TO HAVE THEM
FINALLY CUT THAT CORD.
- HE NEEDS ME.
- HE DOESN'T NEED YOU.
YOU CODDLE HIM.
HE'S TOO OLD
TO GO RUNNING TO HIS MOMMY
WITH ALL HIS PROBLEMS.
- I SEEM TO REMEMBER
A CERTAIN SOMEONE
RUNNING TO MOMMY
WHEN HIS ALGEBRA TEACHER
MADE AN EXAMPLE OF HIM.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD
BEEN SUSPENDED
WHEN ANOTHER BOY
CHEATED OFF HIS TEST.
- TRACY WON'T MARRY ME.
I WON'T GET A JOB, AND--
- [shushing]
- WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
- LET MAMA TAKE CARE OF IT.
I'LL HAVE A LITTLE CHAT
WITH MR. VANDENBOSCH.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY, MR.
VANDENBOSCH WAS NOT IN SCHOOL.
HE WAS NEVER HEARD FROM AGAIN.
- I-I KNOW LIFE IS NOT FAIR
TO WOMEN.
YOUR CHILDREN GROW UP,
AND THEY DON'T NEED YOU ANYMORE.
- AND I SEEM TO REMEMBER
A CERTAIN GROWN MAN
WHO COMPLETELY FELL APART
TWO WEEKS AGO
WHEN I TAPED OVER
THE NOVA SPECIAL
THAT HAD THE GIRL ON IT
HE LIKED.
- THAT WAS BUSTER.
THAT'S MY POINT.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL,
MEANWHILE,
WAS AT
THE FROZEN BANANA STAND
WHEN HE THOUGHT HE SPOTTED
A FAMILIAR FACE:
- POP-POP?
SORRY, MISS.
[chuckling]
POP-POP!
- YOU THINK YOU SAW POP-POP?
- BUT WITH HAIR!
WHICH IS PROBABLY WHY
HE ASKED FOR MY HAIR, REMEMBER?
- GIVE POP-POP YOUR HAIR!
GIVE ME THE HAIR!
- IT ALL ADDS UP.
HE STOLE SOMEBODY'S
HAIR, MADE A WIG,
KNOCKED OUT THE GUARD,
TUNNELED HIS WAY THROUGH
A SEWER LINE,
AND THEN STOPPED
TO GET A CANDY APPLE
ON HIS WAY TO MEXICO!
- OF COURSE!
YOU'RE MOCKING ME.
- [scoffs]
OF COURSE.
- LISTEN, I KNOW WHAT
I SAW, MAEBY.
AND THERE'S
NO OTHER EXPLANATION.
- SO LISTEN.
MY TWIN BROTHER'S IN TOWN.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE CARE OF HIM.
- YOU STILL SEE UNCLE OSCAR?
- TELL YOU WHAT.
GIVE HIM TEN GRAND
FROM THE, UH, NEW CASH.
JUST SEND HIM ON HIS WAY.
- DAD, THE MONEY IS FOR
THE BUSINESS, OKAY?
I'M NOT JUST GONNA
HAND IT ALL OUT.
- MICHAEL!
THIS IS MY BROTHER.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO HAVE A SIBLING
WHO HAS NO SOURCE
OF INCOME EXCEPT FOR YOU?
- JUST ONE? NO.
NO IDEA. IT SOUNDS
WONDERFUL THOUGH.
LOOK, THE BOARD IS WATCHING
EVERY MOVE I MAKE.
ESPECIALLY THAT GUY JORDAN.
HE'S JUST WAITING
FOR ME TO SCREW UP,
SO HE CAN BLOW
THE WHISTLE ON ME.
- WHY DON'T YOU JUST
BUY HIM OUT OF HIS STOCK?
- NO, NO. HE WANTS TWICE
THE VALUE.
BUT--LISTEN.
STOP TELLIN' ME WHAT TO DO
WITH THE MONEY, PLEASE?
I'VE GOT A PLAN
FOR THE BOARD MEETING
THAT'S GONNA TAKE THE
GUN RIGHT OUT OF JORDAN'S HAND.
- LISTEN,
YOU'VE GOT THE MONEY NOW.
AND YOU KNOW MY PRICE.
- YOU DON'T NEED
A WHISTLE-BLOWER AROUND HERE.
- INTERESTING CHOICE OF WORDS,
MR. JORDAN.
HE'S RIGHT. WE DON'T NEED
A WHISTLE-BLOWER.
WE NEED A BUILDING
FULL OF WHISTLE-BLOWERS.
OKAY? WHISTLES.
I WANT THIS PLACE
TO BE HONEST.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHY
I HAD THESE MADE UP FOR US.
WHEN YOU SEE SOMETHING
WRONG, I WA--
[whistles]
THERE YOU GO.
I WANT YOU TO REPORT IT.
I WANT YOU TO--
[whistles]
EXACTLY. JUST LIKE THAT.
I WANT US TO POLICE OURSELVES
AS VIGILANT--
[whistling]
LET'S WAIT TILL SOMETHING
ACTUALLY HAPPENS THOUGH.
OKAY, GOOD FUN.
[chuckles]
ALL RIGHT.
HEY. ENOUGH!
45, 46, 47--
OKAY, THERE'S STILL THREE
WHISTLES LEFT OUT THERE.
WHO'S GOT THE WHISTLES?
[whistles]
- HE KEPT ONE.
- THERE'S A GOOD EXAMPLE
OF WHISTLE-BLOWING, OKAY?
BUT YOU'VE KEPT YOURS,
SO IT'S HURTING YOUR CASE.
- I WAS IN THE BATHROOM
WHEN YOU ASKED FOR IT BACK.
[whistling]
- NO, HE WASN'T.
- IN ANY EVENT,
WE ARE GOING TO BE
RESPONSIBLE WITH THIS MONEY.
- MICHAEL, I HOPE I'M NOT
INTERRUPTING ANYTHING,
BUT I'D LOVE TO GET A HUNK
OF THAT NEW COMPANY MONEY.
[whistling]
- I JUST NEED TO PROVE TO MY
WIFE THAT I CAN ACT LIKE A MAN.
AND IT'S NOT ABOUT SEX.
I DON'T JUST LIE THERE,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
- THAT'S NOT
WHAT I WAS THINKING.
- SORRY, I JUST--
A QUICK QUESTION FOR MICHAEL.
- IS THIS ABOUT THE MONEY?
- NO! [chuckles]
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- I MEAN, IT'S NOT ABOUT MONEY
IN THE SENSE THAT I'M SAYING,
"HERE,
MICHAEL, TAKE SOME MONEY."
IT'S JUST MORE OF A "MAY I HAVE
SOME?" KIND OF VISIT.
- DON'T YOU HAVE A WIFE
THAT YOU CAN ASK NOW?
- SHE LEFT ME.
- FOR TOBIAS?
- FOR ME?
- NO!
SHE DOESN'T EVEN LIKE YOU.
- I'M IN LOVE WITH
YOUR BROTHER-IN-LAW.
- YOU'RE IN LOVE
WITH YOUR OWN BROTHER?
THE ONE IN THE ARMY?
- NO.
YOUR SISTER'S HUSBAND.
- MICHAEL? MICHAEL!
- NO, THAT'S
YOUR SISTER'S BROTHER.
- I'M MY SISTER'S BROTHER.
YOU'RE IN LOVE WITH ME. ME!
- I'M IN LOVE WITH TOBIAS.
- MY BROTHER-IN-LAW?
- I KNOW IT CAN NEVER BE.
SO I'M LEAVING.
I'M ENLISTING IN THE ARMY.
- TO BE WITH YOUR BROTHER.
- NO!
- ANYWAY, I CAN'T BE EXPECTED
TO LIVE ON THE $800-A-MONTH
ARMY-WIFE STIPEND
THAT I'M GONNA GET.
- THEY JUST DON'T
SUPPORT THE SPOUSES.
- YOU DON'T WANT TO END UP
LIKE UNCLE OSCAR, OKAY,
LIVING OFF HANDOUTS
YOUR WHOLE LIFE?
WHY DON'T YOU COME UP
WITH A WAY TO MAKE MONEY?
A SUGGESTION OF SOMETHING
TO INVEST IN
OR MAYBE,
UH, MAYBE A BUSINESS IDEA?
- WELL, I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO REMAKE "ANNIE HALL."
EXCEPT I WOULDN'T WANT TO GET
IN BED WITH A GREEN PRODUCER
LIKE A SOFIA COPPOLA THOUGH.
OH, BUT GIVE ME AN OLD PRO,
LIKE A ROBERT REDFORD?
OH, I'D JUMP INTO BED
WITH HIM IN A SECOND.
AND I WOULDN'T JUST
LIE THERE, MICHAEL BLUTH,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
- ACTUALLY, THAT TIME THAT WAS
WHAT I WAS THINKING.
- [chuckles]
narrator: AND LATER THAT DAY,
MAEBY SPOTTED
SOMETHING INTERESTING.
LINDSAY, MEANWHILE,
ARRIVED AT THE SALON
HOPING TO INCREASE
HER SELF-ESTEEM.
UNFORTUNATELY, HER STYLIST
HAD JUST BEEN CALLED UP
BY HIS RESERVE UNIT.
- WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- I'M NOT ALLOWED TO TELL.
IT'S THE WAR.
- OH, COME ON! THESE SALON
WARS HAVE GOT TO STOP!
- THE WAR, LINDSAY.
THE REAL WAR.
narrator: LINDSAY WAS STUNNED,
NOT JUST THAT SHE WAS LOSING
HER STYLIST,
BUT THAT APPARENTLY,
THERE WAS A WAR GOING ON.
- WELL, I'M PROTESTING THIS WAR.
YOU'RE MY FRIEND,
AND I'M NOT GONNA LET
SHAUNA CUT MY HAIR.
I'M GOING TO TAKE A STAND.
narrator:
AND LINDSAY FOUND A SOLUTION
TO HER SELF-ESTEEM PROBLEM.
GOB AND TOBIAS, MEANWHILE,
WERE BRAINSTORMING
AT A LOCAL COFFEE SHOP.
- I NEED A CUP OF COFFEE
TO FOCUS.
- IT'S SO CROWDED IN HERE.
I CAN'T THINK.
OKAY.
WHAT IS IT THAT PEOPLE NEED?
- PEOPLE LOVE TO CARBO-LOAD.
THE BAGEL PLACE.
- THERE YOU GO.
- HEY, GUYS. WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
- JUST RESEARCHING
OUR INVESTMENT.
- OH, YEAH. COFFEE PLACES.
I'VE THOUGHT ABOUT THESE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU GUYS COME UP WITH A
PROPOSAL, WE'LL TRY ONE.
narrator:
GOB AND TOBIAS
ACCIDENTALLY
HAD MICHAEL ON THE HOOK,
AND THEY DIDN'T WANT
TO BLOW THE DEAL.
- I GUESS THAT'S A RESPONSE.
- HEY, NEPHEW.
- OH, HEY!
[chuckles]
UNCLE OSCAR.
HOW ARE YOU DOIN'?
- WOW, YOU ARE LIKE,
LIKE A ROCK.
- [chuckling, groaning]
- OH, THE TENSION! COME ON.
- OH, OKAY.
THAT'S PLENTY.
- OKAY, RIGHT THERE. THAT'S
THE PANCREAS RIGHT THERE.
- WHAT'S HAPPENING NOW?
[chuckles uneasily]
narrator:
THE TWO MEN RECONNECTED,
NEITHER ONE ANXIOUS TO
BRING UP THE ISSUE AT HAND.
- ONE ON THE LIPS.
- OBVIOUSLY,
DAD'S IN PRISON NOW.
I'M RUNNING THE BUSINESS
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENTLY.
- WELL, YOU DO THE BEST
WITH WHAT YOU HAVE.
- YEAH.
- I HAVE LEMONS,
I MAKE LEMONADE.
- THAT'S A VERY
POSITIVE ATTITUDE.
- BUT I HATE
THE LEMONADE BUSINESS.
I HATE THE GRIND. YOU HAVE TO
GRIND SO MANY [bleep] LEMONS.
- YOU'RE NOT A VERY
METAPHORICAL PERSON, ARE YOU?
- I NEED MONEY.
- I KNOW.
- [sighs] AH, I CANNOT TELL YOU
HOW THAT HAS WEIGHED ON ME.
[passing gas]
MM.
- WHY DON'T WE SIT OVER HERE?
SO I'VE GOT TOO MANY PEOPLE
WATCHING ME TOO CLOSELY.
SO IF YOU'RE WILLING
TO WORK,
OR IF YOU HAVE
SOMETHING OF VALUE--
- THE ONLY THING I HAVE
OF VALUE IS MY LAND.
I COULD GIVE YOU THE RIGHTS
TO "ALL YOU NEED ARE SMILES."
THAT WAS A SONG I WROTE
FOR DAVID CASSIDY;
HE WAS GONNA SING
IT ON THE MIKE DOUGLAS SHOW.
BUT HE WAS TOO EMBARRASSED
TO DO IT
IN FRONT
OF JOHN AND YOKO.
- TELL ME ABOUT THE LAND.
- OH, LAND. IT'S A COUPLE
HUNDRED ACRES OF LEMON GROVES,
RIGHT NEAR CAMP PENDLETON.
- IF YOU'RE WILLING TO PART
WITH THAT LAND, UNCLE OSCAR,
I CAN GUARANTEE YOU A LITTLE BIT
MORE THAN THAT $10,000.
- TO BE HONEST, I'VE OFTEN
THOUGHT OF GIVING IT UP
TO PURSUE MY--MY LOST LOVE.
THE LOVE THAT WAS TAKEN FROM ME.
[passing gas]
- I HOPE THAT WAS
THE ESPRESSO MACHINE.
narrator: MICHAEL MADE THE TRIP
TO SURVEY THE LAND.
IT WAS, INDEED, BEAUTIFUL.
AND THE NEXT DAY, HE WENT
TO HIS FATHER TO TELL HIM.
- YOU GIVE THAT GIFT
TO MY BROTHER?
- GIFT? NO.
I DID NOT GIVE HIM A GIFT.
I TOLD YOU. THE MONEY
WAS FOR INVESTING,
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I DID WITH IT, POP.
- OH, MICHAEL!
THIS GUY HAS GOT
NOTHING IN HIS LIFE.
HE WROTE ONE SONG THAT
MADE JOAN BAEZ CALL HIM
"THE SHALLOWEST MAN
IN THE WORLD."
HE HAS A WORTHLESS PIECE
OF PROPERTY
AND, YES,
A HEAD OF HAIR--
ONLY BECAUSE HE'S NEVER
HAD TO WORK FOR A LIVING.
- WAIT, NOW. WHAT PIECE
OF PROPERTY'S WORTHLESS?
- THE GROVE.
YOU KNOW, WHERE HE LIVES.
I MEAN,
YOU CAN'T BUILD ON IT.
THE GOVERNMENT
HAS AN EASEMENT ON IT.
- DOES OSCAR KNOW THIS?
- OF COURSE HE KNOWS IT.
I MEAN, THEY RUN THEIR--
THEIR TANKS THROUGH THERE.
OCCASIONALLY, THEY STOP
FOR A LITTLE LEMONADE,
BUT WHAT'S THAT?
THAT'S A BUCK FIFTY.
YOU CAN'T MAKE MUCH
FROM THAT.
narrator: INDEED, THE LAND
WAS VALUELESS.
[explosion]
[tank rumbling]
- FELLAS! FELLAS!
- SO TELL ME ABOUT
THIS INVESTMENT YOU MADE.
narrator: BACK AT THE MODEL
HOME, LINDSAY HAD DECIDED
NOT TO TAKE HER STYLIST'S
DEPARTURE LYING DOWN.
- I'M PROTESTING THE WAR.
THERE'S A WAR GOING ON,
YOU KNOW?
- YEAH, I'M THE ONE WHO
TOLD YOU,
AND YOU SAID
IT HAPPENED TEN YEARS AGO.
- HEY, ISN'T THIS THE SAME
SIGN YOU USED
TO PICKET
THE CABLE COMPANY
WHEN THEY DROPPED
THE STYLE NETWORK?
- ACTUALLY, I USED THIS ONE
FOR MICHAEL
WHEN HE WAS TOO CHEAP TO PAY
FOR THE PREMIUM CHANNELS.
BUT I ADDED THE BIT
ABOUT THE STYLISTS.
- YOU KNOW THAT SECRET YOU HAVE?
THE ONE ABOUT THE HAIR THAT
NOBODY'S SUPPOSED TO SEE?
- HAI--
- I SAW IT.
- OH.
- I SAW POP-POP.
- OH, RIGHT.
POP-POP WITH HAIR.
YOU KNOW, I SHOULD TELL
MY DAD ABOUT--
- NO, YOU [bleep].
HE MIGHT NEED US TO
HELP HIM,
SO WE SHOULD GO
CHECK OUT THE PRISON
AND MAKE SURE HE'S NOT THERE.
[door opening]
- OH.
- HEY, YOU KNOW, I GOT CABLE.
YOU WON THAT ONE!
[beeping]
- MICHAEL WAS EMBARRASSED ABOUT
THE BAD INVESTMENT HE'D MADE
AND WAS HOPING
TO KEEP IT A SECRET.
- HI, THIS IS OSCAR. I'M OFF,
PURSUING MY LADY LOVE.
LEAVE A MESSAGE. I'LL GET
BACK TO YOU NEXT SUMMER.
[beeping]
- HEY, IT'S MICHAEL.
I KNOW THAT YOU THINK THAT
YOU'VE DISAPPEARED,
BUT I WILL FIND YOU.
[beeps]
- WHO'S DISAPPEARED?
- NO ONE.
- WHY DO YOU ASK?
HAVE YOU SEEN SOMEONE?
- I'VE SEEN NO ONE.
- THEN YOU HAVEN'T SEEN ANYONE
THAT LOOKS LIKE POP-POP.
- NO. WHY?
HAS SOMEONE WHO LOOKS
LIKE POP-POP DISAPPEARED?
- NO. COURSE NOT.
- HAVE YOU SEEN
THE AGRICULTURAL REPORT?
- NOTHING'S HOTTER THAN COFFEE,
SO THE TREND IS UP.
SO IF WE COULD GET
THAT CHECK FROM YOU--
- I'M NOT JUST GONNA
HAND OUT A CHECK, OKAY?
YOU GOTTA COME UP
WITH AN INVESTMENT PLAN,
YOU GOTTA CALL--
- OH, WE'VE GOT
AN INVESTMENT PLAN.
- "GOBIAS INDUSTRIES."
- GO BIAS.
- HMM?
- AS IN, "GO BUY US
SOME COFFEE."
- IT'S GREAT. LOOKS GOOD.
- SO WHEN DO I START
MAKIN' MY MONEYS?
- WELL, UM, THERE, UH--
THERE MAY NOT BE
AS MUCH INVESTMENT CAPITAL
AS WE THOUGHT.
UH, MONEY'S KIND OF
TIED UP IN THIS LAND DEAL.
- THIS IS THE FIRST ANY
OF US AT GOBIAS INDUSTRIES
HAVE HEARD OF A LAND DEAL.
- WE COULD BORROW ON THAT LAND.
- THERE'S NOT MUCH
TO BORROW AGAINST.
THE DEAL SEEMS TO BE BAD.
IT'S UNCLE OSCAR'S LAND,
AND IT MAY BE WORTHLESS.
- AND THE BOARD OKAYED IT?
- WELL, THEY WEREN'T NOTIFIED.
- DAMN IT! EVERY TIME,
DAD DOES THIS TO US.
- GOB, DAD REALLY WASN'T--
- OH, PLEASE!
HE WENT AROUND YOU.
HE WENT AROUND THE BOARD--
- HE STEAMROLLED GOBIAS.
- YEAH, WHAT
ARE YOU GONNA DO?
- I'M GOING TO GO DOWN
TO THAT PRISON
AND GIVE HIM A PIECE
OF MY MIND.
- HEY, GOB, NO, YOU DON'T NEED
TO DO THAT.
- NO, I'M DOING IT!
- NO, YOU DON'T.
- NO, BECAUSE
YOU'RE IN CHARGE NOW.
AND I'M TELLING HIM THAT.
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
LISTEN, GOB, HE'S HUMAN.
HE'S A HUMAN BEING,
AND LET-LET ME TRY TO GET US
OUT OF THIS, YOU KNOW?
LET ME JUST SEE IF I CAN GET
DAD OUT OF THIS MESS
THAT HE HAS
CREATED FOR HIMSELF, OKAY?
- I'M AFRAID THIS OFFER
COMES OFF THE TABLE
AT MIDNIGHT TONIGHT.
- MAYBE THE WORST BLUFF
I'VE EVER SEEN.
narrator: EVEN THE MEMBERS
OF GOBIAS AGREED ON THAT ONE.
THE NEXT DAY, LINDSAY,
HAVING HEARD
ABOUT A MILITARY EXERCISE,
JOINED A PROTEST GROUP
AND WENT OFF TO EXERCISE HER
OWN FIRST AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
- THIS WAY!
THANK YOU!
RIGHT HERE. THIS WAY.
I ASK YOU TO MAKE SURE
YOU'RE FULLY INSIDE
THE FREE SPEECH ZONE
BEFORE BEGINNING
YOUR PROTEST.
- FREE SPEECH ZONE?
THIS IS WHERE WE'RE
PROTESTING?
THIS ISN'T RIGHT.
WHERE ARE THE CAMERAS?
- THEY'RE IN
THE FREE PRESS ZONE,
AND IF YOU COULD
SAVE YOUR COMMENTS UNTIL
YOU'RE COMPLETELY LOADED
INTO THE CAGE.
- WELL, AT LEAST THE PROCESSION
WILL COME THROUGH HERE.
THEY'LL SEE US PROTEST.
- ACTUALLY, THEY'RE USING
THEIR RIGHT
TO CUT THROUGH
THE LEMON GROVE.
- OKAY, HAVE FUN, ENJOY
YOUR RIGHT TO FREE SPEECH.
THE ARMED FORCES
WELCOMES YOUR DISSENT.
- WELL, HOPEFULLY SOMEBODY WILL
COME BY WE CAN PROTEST.
- MY GRANDKIDS.
WHAT A SURPRISE.
- OH, HE'S HERE.
- OF COURSE I'M HERE.
WHERE ELSE WOULD I BE?
- WELL, WE THOUGHT YOU BROKE
OUT OF PRISON
AND WERE ON THE LAM
WITH STOLEN HAIR.
- DON'T YOU THINK THAT
IF I GOT OUT OF HERE,
I MIGHT WANT TO GO HOME?
- THAT'S WHAT WE THOUGHT.
BUT THEN MY DAD TOLD US ABOUT
THAT LEMON GROVE YOU BOUGHT,
AND WE THOUGHT
YOU WERE GOING THERE.
- YEAH, BUT DON'T WORRY.
WE WOULD NEVER
BLOW THE WHISTLE ON FAMILY.
- WHAT LEMON GROVE?
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL WENT
BACK TO THE BOARD
TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR HIS MISTAKE.
- MY DAD SCREWED UP.
HE BOUGHT SOMETHING
THAT HE SHOULDN'T HAVE.
BUT I GUESS--GUESS
THAT'S WHY HE'S BEHIND BARS.
- YEAH.
AND HE'S NOT ALLOWED TO
CONDUCT ANY BUSINESS FROM THERE.
- [inhales] RIGHT, YEAH.
I WAS INVOLVED.
IT WASN'T ALL HIS DECISION.
YOU SEE, IT WAS HIS IDEA,
AND THEN I CARRIED OUT
THE TRANSACTION.
- THAT'S EVEN WORSE.
CONSPIRACY TO COMMIT FRAUD.
'COURSE, YOU CAN ALWAYS
BUY ME OFF THE BOARD.
- WE DON'T HAVE
THE MONEY ANYMORE.
AND I ASSURE YOU THAT NOTHING
ILLEGAL HAS HAPPENED HERE.
I'VE MISSPOKE.
MY DAD IN NO WAY IS TALKING
ABOUT BUSINESS FROM PRISON.
[knocking]
- [softly] EXCUSE ME.
YOUR FATHER'S
CALLING FROM PRISON.
HE WANTS TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT THE LAND DEAL YOU MADE
WITH HIS BROTHER.
HEY, I FOUND THIS
ON YOUR DESK.
CAN I KEEP THIS?
[whistles]
narrator: BACK
AT THE FREE SPEECH ZONE,
LINDSAY'S PROTEST HAD STARTED
TO GAIN SOME ATTENTION.
BUT NOT FROM ANY
KEY DECISION MAKERS.
- THOUGHT WE WERE SEEIN'
A GAY MARRIAGE.
- WELL, WE CAN STILL
HOSE 'EM DOWN.
- WHAT DO WE WANT?
[indistinct chanting]
WHAT DO WE WANT?
[chanting continues]
[yelling, indistinct]
- WHERE'S EVERYONE GOING?
WHAT, ARE YOU GIVING UP?
- FACE IT, LINDSAY.
THEY'VE WON.
- WELL, I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE!
ALL YOUR WATER'S DOING
IS WHETTING MY APPETITE
FOR PROTEST.
NO HAIR FOR OIL!
- FINE! WE'LL DROWN
YOU OUT WITH MUSIC.
- CRANK IT UP!
I'M IN THE MOOD TO DANCE!
[disco]
[volume increases]
- [singing] BAD GIRLS
TALKIN' 'BOUT THE SAD GIRL.
narrator: AND LINDSAY DISCOVERED
THAT THE ACTIVISM THAT CAME OUT
OF HER DESIRE
FOR PRETTIER HAIR REALLY
DID BOOST HER SELF-ESTEEM.
WHILE MICHAEL,
WITH NOWHERE ELSE TO TURN,
MADE A RARE, UNSOLICITED VISIT
TO HIS MOTHER'S.
- MICHAEL?
- YEAH.
- I HOPE YOU'RE HERE TO BRING ME
A CHECK FOR BUSTER'S SURGERY.
THEY MADE HIM STOP EATING
AFTER MIDNIGHT, AND HE'S HUNGRY,
AND HE'S IN A FOREIGN LAND,
AND HIS JAW IS CLICKING,
AND HE'S SCARED.
- I DON'T HAVE THE MONEY.
ALL RIGHT, MOM?
- THEN WHY ARE YOU HERE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW.
- SO HOW'S WORK?
- IT'S-IT'S NOT GREAT,
MOM, SINCE YOU ASKED.
IT'S-IT'S JUST--IT'S NOT THAT
GREAT, YOU KNOW?
I GOT A BOARD MEMBER
WHO'S TRYING TO EXTORT ME,
AND A SELLER I CAN'T FIND--
THIS WHOLE REAL ESTATE THING
IS A TOTAL MESS--
I GOT DAD COMPLETELY--
- WHAT DID YOUR FATHER DO?
DID HE TRY TO SCREW
SOMETHING UP FOR YOU AGAIN?
- NO, NO.
HE DIDN'T SCREW ANYTHING UP.
I SCREWED SOMETHING UP, MOM.
I-I DID IT, AND DAD IS JUST,
YOU KNOW, FURIOUS AT ME.
AND HE SHOULD BE, YOU KNOW?
HE TOLD ME TO PAY OFF
HIS BROTHER, AND I DIDN'T.
INSTEAD, I BOUGHT
HIS WORTHLESS LAND.
- WITH THE LEMONS
AND THE TANKS?
- I KNOW IT!
FIRST INVESTMENT I MADE
WITH THE COMPANY MONEY,
AND IT'S A TOTAL DISASTER.
THEN I WENT AHEAD AND LIED
ABOUT IT,
WHICH IS GONNA
LET THIS BOARD MEMBER
BRING THE COMPANY DOWN.
I'M GONNA RUIN THIS FAMILY,
MOM.
- [shushing]
- WHAT'S THIS?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
- IT'S GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
- WHY ARE YOU SQUEEZING ME
WITH YOUR BODY?
- IT'S A HUG, MICHAEL.
I'M HUGGING YOU.
- WHY?
- BECAUSE YOU NEED
YOUR MOTHER RIGHT NOW.
- BUT I DON'T GET ALONG
WITH MY--SORRY.
THAT WAS A KNEE JERK.
- MICHAEL.
YOU MADE A MISTAKE.
YOU'RE A HUMAN BEING.
BUT YOU'RE SO FORGIVING
TO EVERYONE ELSE IN THIS FAMILY.
TRY BEING FORGIVING
TO YOURSELF.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
LET MAMA TAKE CARE OF IT.
- NO, NO.
MOM, COME ON. I DON'T
WANT YOU TO DO ANYTHING.
HEY! THIS ISN'T ALGEBRA.
I'M A BIG BOY. MOTHER!
DO NOT MAKE SOMEBODY DIS--
[door closes]
DISAPPEAR.
[phone ringing]
[cartoonish sounds]
[shouting, jeering]
- NOW THERE'S SOMEONE WHO
COULD HAVE USED A GOOD MOTHER.
WHORE!
narrator: AND SO
BEFORE OSCAR COULD LEAVE
TO FIND HIS LADY LOVE--
- OSCAR!
narrator: SHE FOUND HIM.
- LUCILLE!
YOU LOOK FANTASTIC!
YOU STILL HAVE THE NECK
OF A 20-YEAR-OLD.
- AND YOU STILL HAVE
THE HAIR OF A LION.
- [laughing]
- TAKE BACK THE LAND.
- THAT'S IT?
BUT I-I THOUGHT
WE COULD HAVE
THIS BRIEF MOMENT
TO RECONNECT.
- OSCAR. YOUR BROTHER
IS IN JAIL RIGHT NOW.
MY HUSBAND IS IN JAIL.
- [sighing]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
- SO WHAT'S THE RUSH?
narrator: AND THE NEXT DAY--
- MICHAEL!
- HEY, MOM! HI.
LISTEN.
I'M SORRY ABOUT YESTERDAY.
IT WAS A MOMENT OF WEAKNESS.
NOW I-I GOTTA GO INTO
THIS BOARD MEETING.
I'M JUST
GONNA TELL THEM THE TRUTH.
IF THIS GUY JORDAN WANTS
TO TRY TO GET ME FIRED,
THEN MAYBE I DESERVE IT.
- HE'S GONE.
WE BOUGHT OUT HIS SHARES.
- WITH WHAT?
- WITH THE MONEY YOU TRIED TO
SPEND ON THAT LEMON GROVE.
- YOU GOT IT BACK. HOW?
- [shushing]
- YOU KNOW ABOUT WHAT I WAS
SAYING
ABOUT HOW PEOPLE
OUTLIVE THEIR USEFULNESS?
THAT WAS OUT OF LINE.
- I KNOW.
BUT YOU MADE A GOOD POINT.
MAYBE I DO NEED SOMETHING
TO OCCUPY MY TIME,
OTHER THAN MY CHILDREN.
- WELL, IF YOU DO WANT
TO SPEND IT TOGETHER,
IT'S FINE WITH ME.
- I'M SO GLAD TO HEAR THAT.
- [sighs]
- ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET THIS
MEETING STARTED.
WHY HAVE WE BEEN SPENDING
SO MUCH MONEY ON WHISTLES?
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL FINDS HAVING HIS MOTHER
ON THE BOARD PROBLEMATIC.
- WE HAVE TO BE COURAGEOUS.
- I REMEMBER A CERTAIN YOUNG
MAN WHO USED TO SAY
"BUT I DON'T HAVE BAD DREAMS
IN YOUR BED!"
[laughing wildly]
- THAT WAS BUSTER.
narrator: LINDSAY FINDS
HER TRUE CALLING:
- I WANT TO BE
A CAGE DANCER.
[laughing]
narrator:
AND OSCAR COMES A-COURTIN'.
- [singing] ALL YOU NEED ARE
SMILES
- WHAT'S THAT RACKET?
- [singing] LOTS AND LOTS OF
SMILEY SMILES
YOUR SWEET PEA MOUTH
GOES NORTH NOT SOUTH
AND JUST SMILES