male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL WAS HEADING OFF TO WORK
WHEN HIS SON, GEORGE MICHAEL,
REMINDED HIM
OF A YEARLY TRADITION.
- HEY, DON'T FORGET ME.
- FOR WHAT?
- IT'S BRING YOUR DAUGHTER
TO WORK DAY.
AND UNLESS YOU HAD A DAUGHTER
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT,
I'M YOUR GIRL.
narrator: MICHAEL
HAD FIRST MADE THIS JOKE
WHEN GEORGE MICHAEL WAS SIX.
- WELL, SHE'S NOT MY DAUGHTER,
BUT IT'S ABOUT AS CLOSE
AS I'M GONNA GET.
- I'M A GOOD LITTLE GIRL.
narrator: IT WAS A JOKE
MICHAEL WAS STARTING
TO GROW CONCERNED ABOUT AS IT
HAD NOT WORN WELL WITH AGE.
- HEY, DAD.
THEY'RE OUT OF SANITARY NAPKINS
IN THE LADIES' WASHROOM.
[laughing]
- WEIRD KID.
- I DON'T THINK THIS YEAR'S
SUCH A GOOD IDEA.
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE GETTING OLDER AND--
- YEAH, RIGHT, PRETTY SOON
I'M GOING TO
HAVE TO START WEARING A BRA.
RIGHT, DAD?
ALL RIGHT, GIVE ME ONE MINUTE.
- REALLY, LET'S NOT THIS YEAR.
I CANNOT KILL THIS JOKE.
HEY, SHOULDN'T YOU
BE GETTING DRESSED?
- NOPE, GOING WITH MY DAD
TO WORK TODAY.
- HEY, PEANUT BUTTER CUP.
- THIS IS WORK?
WATCHING ENTERTAINMENT NEWS?
- WELL, EXCUSE ME, MICHAEL,
FOR NOT RAISING THE PERFECT
DAUGHTER THAT YOU DID.
I INDULGED THIS RITUAL
FOR YEARS IN BOSTON.
narrator:
AS A PSYCHOTHERAPIST,
TOBIAS WAS ON THE FOREFRONT
OF THE SELF-ESTEEM MOVEMENT.
- BUT THERE'S, LIKE,
THIS LONGING, THIS PULL.
I MEAN, DOES THAT MAKE ME,
YOU KNOW, LIKE SOME KIND OF--
- HOMOSEXUAL.
- MAEBY, PLEASE.
- SHE'S RIGHT, THOUGH.
YOU PROBABLY ARE A HOMOSEXUAL.
- SO, MAEBY, THIS IS WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA DO THIS YEAR?
YOU'RE GONNA WATCH HIM WATCH TV?
- [snoring]
- OH, BLESS HER.
IT'S LIKE SHE KNEW
WHAT I WAS GOING TO DO NEXT.
- IT'S HERE!
"GIRLS WITH LOW SELF-ESTEEM:
NEWPORT BEACH."
FROM THE ACT I DID
ON THE BEACH OVER SPRING BREAK.
- narrator: GOB HAD
RECENTLY DONE A MAGIC SHOW
WHERE HE HAD MADE THE BLUTH
FAMILY YACHT DISAPPEAR.
IT WAS SPRING BREAK,
AND THE ACT WAS FILMED
FOR THE POPULAR VIDEO SERIES,
"GIRLS WITH LOW SELF-ESTEEM."
- THIS PUTS ME BACK ON TOP
OF THE OLD MAGIC CAREER, THOUGH.
- HANG ON, GOB,
YOU'RE NOT GONNA PUT THAT IN.
THERE'S NUDITY ON THAT.
MAEBY, WHY DON'T YOU GO
UPSTAIRS AND GET DRESSED?
- I MUST WARN YOU, MICHAEL.
SHE DOESN'T RESPOND WELL
TO STRICT DIRECTIVES.
- ALL RIGHT.
- THAT WAS ODD.
- NOT REALLY.
KIDS LOVE BOUNDARIES.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THESE GIRLS.
IS THIS WHAT YOU WANT?
- OH, GOD, NO.
- 'CAUSE THIS COULD BE
WHERE YOUR DAUGHTER IS HEADED.
- OH, NO, NO.
I DON'T WANT THIS
FOR MAEBY EITHER, NO.
- OH, HERE IT IS.
HERE IT IS.
- IT WAS A WILD TIME
ON THE BEACH,
AND IF YOU LIKE MAGIC,
LOOK AWAY.
THE ONLY THING THIS GUY COULD
MAKE FLY AWAY WAS THE CROWD.
- DOUCHE CHILL.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY USED THAT PART.
THE ONE PART
WHERE I SCREW UP.
IT'S NOT LIKE
THEY USED THE PART
WHERE I MADE
THE YACHT DISAPPEAR.
- SUNK THE YACHT.
BLEW IT UP, SUNK IT.
- WE SURE DID.
- WE? NO.
I GAVE YOU PERMISSION
TO USE THE YACHT.
YOU BLEW IT UP.
- YEAH, WELL, IF YOU GIVE
SOMEONE PERMISSION
TO USE A TISSUE, YOU CAN'T BE
UPSET IF THEY BLOW THEIR NOSE.
RIGHT?
I MEAN, RIGHT?
- [snoring]
- LINDSAY, NEW OUTFIT?
- THIS?
NO, I'VE HAD THIS FOR YEARS.
I THINK IT'S
A HAND-ME-DOWN FROM MOM.
- GOT A PRICE TAG RIGHT THERE.
- IS THERE?
OH, I GUESS SHE WANTED ME
TO HAVE SOMETHING NEW.
SWEET OLD THING.
- ONLY TWO OF THOSE WORDS
DESCRIBE MOM,
SO I KNOW
YOU'RE LYING TO ME.
- FINE, I BOUGHT IT
BEFORE WE WENT BROKE, OKAY?
I JUST HAVEN'T WORN IT YET.
- WHAT ABOUT
THE OUTFIT YESTERDAY?
- OLD THING GAVE IT TO ME.
- WHERE ARE YOU
GETTING ALL THE MONEY?
- IT'S NOT COSTING YOU ANYTHING,
MICHAEL.
- UNLESS YOU'RE STEALING OR
WORKING, I'M PRETTY SURE IT IS.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
I STOLE IT.
narrator: IN FACT, LINDSAY,
TIRED OF WEARING
LAST YEAR'S FASHIONS, WENT TO
AN UPSCALE DEPARTMENT STORE
AND, IN A MOMENT OF DESPERATION,
APPLIED FOR A JOB.
- CAN I HAVE
A JOB APPLICATION, PLEASE?
narrator: BUT SHE WAS ASHAMED
OF BEING A SHOPGIRL
AND WAS RELIEVED WHEN MICHAEL
GAVE HER THE OUT.
- WELL, THEY EXPECT A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF THEFT, MICHAEL.
IT'S BUILT INTO THE PRICE.
IF I DIDN'T TAKE IT,
THEN PEOPLE WOULD BE
OVERPAYING FOR NOTHING.
- SO YOU'RE TELLING ME THAT YOU
WALKED INTO A STORE
AND, WITHOUT ANYONE NOTICING,
TOOK AN ENTIRE OUTFIT?
THERE'S NO WAY THAT YOU COULD
DO SLEIGHT-OF-HAND THAT WELL.
I DON'T EVEN THINK
THAT I COULD DO IT.
- YEAH, I'VE SEEN YOUR TAPE.
LINDSAY, THIS IS APPALLING.
- WHAT'D YOU USE
FOR MISDIRECTION?
- MISDIRECTION?
- YEAH, I MEAN,
IF YOU'RE SO GOOD AT MAGIC,
WHAT'D YOU HAVE THEM LOOKING AT
TO DIVERT THEIR ATTENTION?
- I DON'T KNOW--
MY ASS.
- MY ASS; YOU'RE LYING.
- NO, I'M NOT.
- YOU'RE GONNA TAKE THAT BACK.
THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH YOU.
YOU'RE NOT MY FATHER.
- NO, OUR FATHER IS IN PRISON
FOR STEALING, REMEMBER?
WHICH MIGHT NOT BE A BAD PLACE
FOR YOU TO GET USED TO.
- MICHAEL, IT WAS SHOPLIFTING,
AND I'M WHITE.
I THINK I'M GOING TO BE OKAY.
- SHOPLIFTING?
COOL, CAN YOU TAKE ME?
- NO, HEY, NOT COOL.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
MAEBY, YOU'RE GONNA
COME WITH ME TO WORK TODAY.
YOU'RE GONNA BE MY DAUGHTER.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE A ROLE MODEL
IN YOUR LIFE WHO IS HONEST,
WHO DOESN'T STEAL,
DOESN'T LIE, AND, I DON'T KNOW,
WATCH ENTERTAINMENT NEWS.
- MICHAEL,
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT, OKAY?
SHE'S NOT GONNA GO WITH YOU.
- OKAY.
- GREAT.
- THAT WAS ODD.
- I'M GOING TO TEACH YOU TWO
A LITTLE SOMETHING
ABOUT HANDS-ON PARENTING.
- HEY, DAD!
DO YOU THINK THIS PURSE
GOES WITH THIS OUTFIT?
WHERE'D MY DAD GO?
- DOUCHE CHILL.
narrator:
AND SO MICHAEL TOOK HIS NIECE
TO BRING YOUR DAUGHTER
TO WORK DAY.
- UH, YOU CAN JUST DROP ME OFF
AT THE MALL.
- OH, NO, YOU'RE--
YOU'RE REALLY COMING WITH ME.
YOU'RE GONNA LEARN A LITTLE
SOMETHING ABOUT HARD WORK.
HEY, MAEBY!
MAEBY!
[tires screeching]
- OKAY, SO YOU CAN
RUN FASTER THAN ME.
BUT YOU CAN'T MAKE ME WORK.
- NO ONE'S MAKING YOU
DO ANYTHING, YOU KNOW.
IT'S JUST A CHANCE FOR US
TO SPEND SOME TIME TOGETHER.
LEARN ABOUT BUSINESS.
YOU KNOW, YOU MIGHT FIND
THAT YOU'RE GOOD AT THINGS
YOU DIDN'T EVEN KNOW ABOUT.
SEE THAT?
WHO KNEW YOU WERE
SUCH A GOOD LITTLE CLIMBER?
NOW LISTEN,
LET'S MAKE THIS FUN, OKAY?
[cell phone ringing]
WE'RE FAMILY.
WHAT IS BETTER THAN
HANGING OUT WITH FAMILY, HMM?
OH--IT'S MY MOTHER.
[phone beeps]
HI.
- SHE CALLED YOU, HUH?
I GUESS I'M NOT GOOD ENOUGH
TO BE HER HUSBAND.
- WHAT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- OKAY.
MOTHER WANTS SOMEONE TO GO
TO MY SOCCER GAME WITH.
SHE DON'T WANT
OTHER SOCCER MOMS TO THINK
THAT SHE A SINGLE MOTHER.
SHE OLD SCHOOL.
- I LIKED IT BETTER
WHEN HE JUST SAID ANNYONG.
HEY, MOM, WHY CAN'T BUSTER
PRETEND TO BE YOUR ESCORT?
THAT'S THE WAY HE'S GOT IT
IN ALL HIS CARTOONS.
- THEY ALREADY KNOW HE'S MY SON.
- I WOULDN'T GO
EVEN IF YOU ASKED.
YOU DIDN'T LET ME PLAY SOCCER
AS A CHILD.
WHY SHOULD I HAVE TO SIT
AND CHEER ANNYONG?
ANNYONG NEVER CHEERS ME.
- GO, FATTY.
- [grunting, crashing]
- STOP IT!
HE'S YOUR LITTLE BROTHER!
- NO, HE'S NOT!
I CAME OUT OF YOU!
HE DIDN'T!
- CAN YOU NOT CALL ME WITH
THESE LITTLE THINGS, PLEASE?
THE OFFICE IS A MESS.
I STILL HAVEN'T REPLACED KITTY.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD RECENTLY FIRED
HIS FATHER'S
LONGTIME ASSISTANT, KITTY.
- DID YOU HEAR THAT EVERYONE?
MICHAEL BLUTH IS THREATENING ME!
- SHH, SHH, SHH.
narrator:
IT HAD NOT BEEN A CLEAN BREAK.
- SO, I'VE GOT
A LOT OF WORK TO DO.
PLUS, IT'S BRING
YOUR DAUGHTER TO WORK DAY.
- OH, WHERE IS GEORGE MICHAEL?
- I TOLD HIM NOT TO COME.
I-I THOUGHT IT WAS MORE
IMPORTANT TO BRING MAEBY THIS--
[both grunting]
DAMN IT, CAN YOU JUST
FIND SOMEBODY ELSE, PLEASE,
TO LOOK LIKE YOUR HUSBAND?
narrator:
IN FACT, THERE WAS SOMEONE ELSE
WHO LOOKED LIKE
LUCILLE'S HUSBAND--
HIS TWIN BROTHER, OSCAR.
- LUCILLE.
narrator: AND ALTHOUGH
SHE KNEW IT WAS WRONG
TO PLAY WITH HIS HEART--
- OSCAR, IT'S LUCILLE.
narrator: SHE REALLY DIDN'T WANT
TO GO TO THE SOCCER GAME ALONE.
- [speaking softly]
I NEED YOU.
[grunting]
narrator:
AND BACK AT THE MODEL HOME,
THREE OF THE BLUTH MEN
STRUGGLED WITH THEIR MANLINESS.
- YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
I MAKE THESE JOKES
ABOUT BEING A DAUGHTER
FOR MY DAD.
AND I KNOW I'M A MAN.
IT'S HIS INSECURITY, NOT MINE.
- THERE'S NO SECURITY
AT THAT STORE.
THAT'S HOW
SHE WAS ABLE TO SHOPLIFT.
PROBABLY DON'T EVEN HAVE
A REGULAR SECURITY GUARD.
- WELL, OF COURSE I COULD GET
A JOB AS A SECURITY GUARD.
I MEAN, IF I HAVE TO HAVE
A JOB TO IMPRESS MY DAUGHTER.
IF SHE NEEDS
SOMETHING THAT BUTCH.
- YEAH.
I CAN HANG OUT WITH MY UNCLES.
I MEAN, THREE MEN.
WHAT'S BUTCHER THAN THAT?
- I'M GOING TO THE MALL.
- ME TOO.
- YEAH, MAYBE A NEW PAIR
OF SHOES WILL CHEER ME UP.
- AND NOW I'M FILLING OUT
AN EXPENSE REPORT,
SO I CAN SLEEP WELL AT NIGHT,
KNOWING THAT I HAVE BEEN HONEST.
YOU'RE NOT ASLEEP.
- I WAS.
- YOU WERE NOT.
- YOU KNOW, I WOULD LIKE TO SEE
IF YOU COULD GO ONE DAY
WITHOUT TELLING A LIE.
JUST ONE WHOLE DAY
WITHOUT BEING LIKE YOUR MOM.
- WHAT'S IN IT FOR ME IF I DO?
- YOU'LL WIN MY RESPECT.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- AND 50 BUCKS.
- FINE.
I'LL DO IT IF YOU DO IT.
- THAT-A-GIRL.
THIS IS GONNA BE FUN.
- I WIN.
- WE'RE LOOKING
FOR MICHAEL BLUTH?
- THAT'S ME.
I'M MICHAEL BLUTH.
- I'M OFFICER TAYLOR.
THIS IS OFFICER CARTER.
OUR DAUGHTERS,
TAMMY AND MONI--
OH, GOD, WHAT--
WHERE DID THEY GO?
- I'M ON IT.
- HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
- WELL, WE'RE HERE INVESTIGATING
THE DISAPPEARANCE
OF KITTY SANCHEZ.
APPARENTLY, YOU'RE THE LAST
PERSON TO SEE HER...ALIVE...
OR AROUND TOWN OR WHATEVER.
- I DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT.
I-I DO KNOW THAT, UH,
SHE WAS MY SECRETARY,
UH, BUT SHE LEFT.
OR I-I FIRED HER.
- DID YOU EVER THREATEN HER?
- NO, NO, GOD, NO.
OF COURSE NOT.
- MICHAEL BLUTH
IS THREATENING ME!
- I DID--I THREATENED HER
AT A RESTAURANT.
BUT, YOU KNOW
IT'S A RESTAURANT, SO...
- YEP.
- CERTAINLY SHE'S
BEEN SEEN SINCE THEN?
- NOT ALIVE...
OR DEAD OR WHATEVER.
WE'D LOVE TO SPEAK WITH YOU
DOWN AT THE STATION.
- SURE, UH, YOU KNOW,
I-I-I'M HAPPY TO COOPERATE,
BUT I REALLY DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING MORE THAN YOU KNOW.
I CERTAINLY DIDN'T--
DIDN'T KILL HER
AND DROP HER IN A BACK BAY.
BOY, I HOPE THAT'S
NOT WHAT HAPPENED TO HER.
- I'M SURE IT ISN'T.
PLEASE SEND OFFICER DAVIS AND
LITTLE HANNA TO THE BACK BAY.
- SO YOU KILLED KITTY, HUH?
- NO, I DIDN'T KILL KITTY.
BUT I WILL GO DOWN
TO THE STATION
AND ANSWER
THOSE NICE MEN'S QUESTIONS.
YOU KNOW WHY?
'CAUSE I HAVE
NO SECRETS TO HIDE,
BECAUSE I'M AN HONEST MAN.
[laughter]
AND APPARENTLY A FUN ONE.
LET'S GO SEE WHAT'S
GOING ON IN THE BACK ROOM.
- WERE THOSE THE LAST WORDS
KITTY EVER HEARD?
- NO, I WILL NOT KISS HER.
- HEY, HEY, GUYS,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IT'S BRING
YOUR DAUGHTER TO WORK DAY.
- YEAH, THAT'S MY CAITLIN.
- OKAY.
THERE IS WORK TO BE DONE.
CAN WE GET BACK TO IT?
THANK YOU.
OH, AND HAS ANYBODY, UH,
SEEN OR HEARD FROM KITTY LATELY?
- I THINK THAT'S HER
RIGHT BEHIND YOU THERE.
- OH, MY GOD.
THAT IS KITTY.
- AND THAT'S THE BOAT
THAT UNCLE GOB BLEW UP.
HEY, NOW YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO TELL THEM AT THE STATION.
narrator: TOBIAS SOUGHT OUT
A SECURITY POSITION
AT THE NEARBY MALL.
- I DO KNOW STAGE COMBAT
IF THE PARTNER IS WILLING
AND A BIT MORE PETITE THAN I.
BUT I HAVE A DAUGHTER
TO IMPRESS, AND I NEED THIS JOB.
- WELL, IT'S GONNA BE
A COUPLE OF DAYS
BEFORE WE CAN
GET YOU A GUN LICENSE,
SO YOU'LL HAVE TO USE MINE.
- WOW!
[chuckles]
narrator: MEANWHILE,
GOB HAD TAKEN GEORGE MICHAEL
ON A MYSTERIOUS ERRAND.
- WHAT ARE WE GETTING?
IS IT SOMETHING
FOR A MAGIC TRICK?
- IN A WAY.
- THAT'S COOL.
YOU KNOW, IT'S SO GREAT
TO BE HANGING OUT WITH YOU.
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS
THAT I CAN TALK TO YOU ABOUT
THAT I CAN'T REALLY WITH MY DAD.
LIKE, UH, WERE--WERE YOU EVER
AWKWARD AROUND GIRLS?
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
LIKE IF THERE WERE
THREE OF US
AND I DIDN'T
KNOW WHERE TO START?
NO, I THINK
I DID PRETTY WELL.
- [chuckles]
- NOT A LOT OF COMPLAINTS,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
AT LEAST NOT FROM THE GIRL.
- YOU'RE SAYING
I SHOULD JUST BE MYSELF?
- AND HE HAD TO DRIVE HER HOME.
SO I THINK I DID PRETTY GOOD.
PRETTY DAMN GOOD.
HEY, GUY.
- YES, SIR?
- HOW MANY MICE WILL $13 BUY?
narrator: AND AT THE PRISON,
GEORGE SR. HAD A SURPRISE VISIT.
- I JUST WANTED TO CHECK IN
AND MAKE SURE YOU'RE AWARE
THAT YOUR BAN ON ORGANIZED
SPORTS IN THIS FAMILY
HAS BEEN VIOLATED.
- A BAN ON ORGANIZED SPORTS?
- YOU KNOW, HOW YOU WOULDN'T
LET ME SIGN UP FOR ANYTHING
WHEN I WAS A KID.
- IS THAT WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
THINKING ALL THESE YEARS?
NO, NO.
YOU WERE--YOU WERE JUST A TURD
OUT THERE, YOU KNOW?
YOU COULDN'T KICK
AND YOU COULDN'T RUN.
YOU KNOW,
YOU WERE JUST A-A TURD.
- PRISON HAS DESTROYED
THE WAY YOU TALK.
IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES TO
IMPRESS THESE GUYS AROUND HERE,
THEN THEY ARE NOT YOUR FRIENDS.
ANYWAY,
ANNYONG'S PLAYING SOCCER,
BUT I GUESS I SHOULD
JUST IGNORE IT.
LOOK THE OTHER WAY
AS MOM AND UNCLE OSCAR
AND ANNYONG
HAVE THE PERFECT LITTLE FAMILY--
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
OSCAR?
MY BROTHER, OSCAR?
OSCAR'S BEEN COMING AROUND?
- NO TOUCHING!
- NO TOUCHING.
NO TOUCHING.
YOU LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'VE GOT TO TAKE CARE
OF THIS OSCAR SITUATION.
YOU GET HIM
OUT OF THERE, ALL RIGHT?
YOU MAKE HIM WISH
THAT HE'D NEVER SHOWN
THAT LUDICROUS HEAD OF HAIR
AND THAT NICE FACE OF HIS.
- I WILL DO IT, DAD.
- GOOD; PUT HER THERE.
- NO TOUCHING!
- OH!
- HER SELF-ESTEEM
IS THROUGH THE ROOF.
narrator: AND MICHAEL ARRIVED AT
THE POLICE STATION WITH MAEBY.
- I GOT HERE AS QUICKLY
AS I COULD.
- I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU HAD A DAUGHTER.
- I DON'T.
- I THOUGHT YOU WANTED ME
TO CALL YOU DADDY?
- WHY DON'T YOU WAIT
FOR DADDY IN THE CAR?
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO WE HAVE HERE?
- GOB SUNK THE YACHT.
LAST TIME KITTY WAS SEEN,
SHE WAS GETTING ONTO IT.
IT'S ON TAPE.
- OOH, DID YOU SEE THIS?
- YEP.
- OOH!
CHILLS.
WHERE DO I KEEP GETTING
THESE BRUISES?
- BARRY!
- OKAY,
UNTIL WE GET ALL THE FACTS,
DON'T SAY ANYTHING
THAT CAN INCRIMINATE YOU.
OR ME.
JUST TRY TO KEEP ME OUT OF THIS.
LIE.
BOTH OF YOU.
- NO, WHAT ARE YOU TALK--
WE DON'T LIE IN THIS FAMILY.
MAEBY, WHY DON'T YOU
GET A SODA?
- OKAY.
- IF I LIE IN FRONT OF HER,
IT COSTS ME 50 BUCKS.
I DO THINK THAT WE SHOULD LIE.
narrator:
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY WAS AT WORK
AND STARTING TO GET JEALOUS
THAT HER DAUGHTER
WAS AT WORK WITH MICHAEL.
- OH, HELLO, MICHAEL.
I KNOW YOU THINK
I'M SUCH A HORRIBLE MOTHER,
BUT I WAS JUST SEEING HOW
MY DAUGHTER WAS DOING AT WORK.
- UH, SHE'S, UM, SHE'S MAKING
LOTS OF FRIENDS ALREADY.
CAN YOU HELP ME THERE, PLEASE?
narrator:
IT WAS AT THIS MOMENT
THAT GOB AND GEORGE MICHAEL
ARRIVED AT THE STORE.
- YOU KNOW, SAY WHAT YOU WILL
ABOUT AMERICA--
13 BUCKS STILLS GETS
YOU A HELL OF A LOT OF MICE.
- WHO SAID ANYTHING BAD
ABOUT AMERICA?
- NO, WELL, I MEANT--
SO WHAT ARE THE MICE FOR?
- OH, NO, THAT'S JUST
FOR MISDIRECTION.
WE'LL SEE WHO
THE SLEIGHT-OF-HAND ARTIST IS
IN THIS FAMILY.
OKAY, NOW, WHEN I YELL "MICE!"
I WANT YOU TO OPEN THIS BOX,
AND I'M GONNA START STUFFING
SOME SHIRTS DOWN YOUR PANTS.
- SHIRTS?
GOB, ARE WE SHOPLIFTING?
- MICE!
CALL SECURITY!
- MICHAEL, I'M NOT AS BAD
AN INFLUENCE AS YOU THINK I AM.
- WELL, YOU'RE NOT A GREAT ONE.
YOU'RE A CRIMINAL, LINDSAY.
WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE
DOES THAT SEND?
- BLUTH.
WE'RE READY TO QUESTION YOU NOW.
- THAT'S WHAT I AM, MICHAEL.
I'M A SHOPLIFTER!
I'VE GOT A WHOLE BAG
OF CLOTHES I SHOPLIFTED.
narrator:
BUT TOBIAS WAS NOW A GUARD.
- [screams]
narrator:
AND A SURPRISINGLY CATLIKE ONE.
- WOW, I GUESS WE DIDN'T
NEED THE MICE.
- FREEZE, [bleep].
narrator: WHILE THE REST
OF THE BLUTHS WERE
IN POLICE CUSTODY, LUCILLE WAS
WITH HER BROTHER-IN-LAW.
- I AM BLOWN AWAY THAT YOU--
THAT YOU CALLED ME
AND THAT WE'RE--WE'RE TOGETHER.
AND MY CAMPER MADE IT
ALL THE WAY UP HERE.
DO YOU THINK IT'S SAFE
OVER THERE?
BECAUSE I ONLY HAVE
A HANGER FOR A LOCK.
- WHAT ARE THEY GONNA TAKE,
THE ONE CAN OF COMET
YOU'VE GOT IN THERE?
- OH, YOUR TONGUE IS AS SHARP
AS YOUR BODY IS STILL TAUT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OSCAR, THIS IS A CHILDREN'S
SOCCER GAME, NOT WOODSTOCK.
- THAT WAS ANOTHER ERA, HUH?
THE MUSIC AND THE POT.
WILL YOU EXCUSE ME?
I NEED TO GO TO MY CAMPER
FOR JUST A QUICK SEC.
[whistle blows]
- OPEN.
- HEY, UNCLE.
- HEY, BUSTER.
NO, NO, NO.
- NO, NO, NO.
NO! NO! NO!
I CAME HERE TO SAY SOMETHING.
YOU DO NOT BELONG HERE.
MY MOTHER'S BEEN SPOKEN FOR.
YOU KNOW, I MAY NEVER HAVE
PLAYED ORGANIZED SPORTS,
BUT I AM A MAN.
- BUSTER.
- AND I'M AFRAID I'M GONNA
HAVE TO ASK YOU TO LEAVE.
- OKAY.
BUT, UH, I NEVER MEANT
TO BREAK UP YOUR FAMILY.
YOUR MOM
CALLED ME FOR A REASON.
AND I DON'T THINK SHE'S HAPPY.
- NO, SHE'S HAPPY.
SHE'S JUST MEAN ALL THE TIME.
[moans]
UH, NO, NO, NO, UNCLE,
LET ME GET YOU.
I'M A MAN.
MOVE.
narrator: MICHAEL SUBMITTED
TO THE DETECTIVE'S QUESTIONS.
- YOU HAVEN'T SEEN
ANY EVIDENCE OF MS. SANCHEZ
OR WHERE SHE MIGHT HAVE GONE?
- I HAVE, UH, NO IDEA.
NONE.
- ARE YOU WILLING TO TAKE
A POLYGRAPH TO THAT EFFECT?
- ARE YOU NUTS?
- NOT WITHOUT A BETTER LAWYER.
- YOU'RE HOLDING OUT ON US!
[baby crying]
FANTASTIC.
NOW EMMA'S AWAKE.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
LET ME TAKE CARE OF THIS.
- PLEASE.
- [singing]
TOO RA LOO RA LOO RA
- KITTY HAD EVIDENCE
AGAINST YOUR FATHER,
AND YOU DIDN'T
WANT THAT TO COME OUT.
BUT NOW YOU'VE GOT
BIGGER PROBLEMS, MY FRIEND.
SO WHY DON'T WE MAKE A DEAL?
- WHAT, I GIVE YOU EVIDENCE
AGAINST MY FATHER,
AND YOU PRETEND
THAT I DIDN'T KILL KITTY?
I MEAN,
I-I DIDN'T KILL KITTY.
[cell phone ringing]
HELLO?
OH, HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL.
UH, I'M SORRY.
IN YOUR PANTS?
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
UM, MY SON HAS AN EMERGENCY.
- YOU KNOW,
THERE'S A GROVER BOOK:
"I CAN'T HOLD IT IN."
WORKED FOR US.
narrator: BUSTER EMERGED
FROM OSCAR'S TRAILER
WITH A NEWFOUND
SENSE OF MANLINESS
AND THEN RECEIVED
A SERENDIPITOUS GIFT.
- KICK IT BACK!
- IF YOU CAN KICK, FATTY.
- I'M A MAN.
[kids yelling]
[screaming]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GET OFF THE FIELD!
ARE YOU CRAZY?
- [laughing]
[all groaning]
[slow clapping]
narrator: AND BUSTER REALIZED
HE MAY HAVE JUST SCARED AWAY
A MAN WHO SUPPORTED HIM
IN THE WAY HE'D ALWAYS HOPED
HIS OWN FATHER WOULD.
AND MICHAEL HEADED
OVER TO THE MALL.
- SO WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
- HEY, DAD, I DIDN'T KNOW
WE WERE SHOPLIFTING, OKAY?
- SHOPLIFTING?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU, GOB?
- WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH ME?
SHE'S THE SHOPLIFTER!
- I WASN'T SHOPLIFTING,
YOU TWIT.
- YES, THANKS TO ME.
- NO.
I WORK HERE.
[all gasp]
AT LEAST I USED TO.
THEY FIRED ME
BECAUSE THEY THOUGHT
I WAS HELPING
THIS IDIOT SHOPLIFT.
ALSO, THEY SAID I WASN'T
A VERY GOOD SALESGIRL.
- [chuckles]
YOU CAN'T BE SERIOUS?
- A SALESGIRL.
I KNEW IT!
I KNEW YOU COULDN'T PULL IT OFF.
THERE'S ONLY ONE MAGICIAN
IN THIS FAMILY, AND THAT IS ME.
- AND YOU GOT CAUGHT
BY A 13-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
- [chuckles]
- YOU KNOW, THIS IS WHY
I'M CONSTANTLY ASKING YOU
TO STAY AWAY FROM MY SON.
- YEAH, WELL, IT'S NOT LIKE
YOU WERE THERE
TO SPEND ANY TIME
WITH ME, DAD.
BECAUSE I'M NOT DAUGHTER
ENOUGH FOR YOU.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, UM,
I'M ALWAYS THERE FOR YOU, OKAY?
IT'S JUST YOU'RE GETTING
A LITTLE TOO MANLY
FOR BRING
YOUR DAUGHTER TO WORK DAY.
- DAD,
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT FUNNY.
- I ALSO WANTED TO GIVE MAEBY
A GOOD ROLE MODEL FOR A CHANGE.
- YEAH, WELL, I GUESS,
YOU LOOKING OUT FOR HER
IS PROBABLY
SOMETHING SHE COULD USE.
- WHERE IS MAEBY?
narrator: MICHAEL REALIZED
HE HAD TO GET
TO THE POLICE STATION
BEFORE THEY GOT AHOLD OF MAEBY,
TO WHOM HE'D PROMISED $50
TO TELL THE TRUTH.
- UH, I'VE PUT A BOUNTY
ON MY OWN HEAD.
narrator: BUT MAEBY'S INSTINCTS
TO LIE RETURNED.
- HEY, YOU CAN'T GO IN THERE.
- NO, IT'S OKAY.
I'M DETECTIVE FELLOWS' DAUGHTER.
- OH, OH, SORRY.
IT'S FOUR-THREE-FIVE.
AND THAT OPENS
ANY DOOR IN THE BUILDING.
- GREAT.
THANKS.
narrator: AND IT WAS THERE
THAT MAEBY DISCOVERED
THE KEY
TO MICHAEL'S FREEDOM.
- WELL, I APPRECIATE
YOUR HONESTY.
- MAEBY.
WHAT--WHAT--WHAT'D SHE SAY?
- I SAID THERE'S A TAPE
OF KITTY GETTING ON THE BOAT,
AND THAT YOU GUYS BLEW IT UP.
I TOLD THEM THE TRUTH,
LIKE YOU TOLD ME.
- THAT-A-GIRL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S, UH, THAT'S THE TRUTH.
THAT'S EVERYTHING THAT WE KNOW.
- YOU'RE FREE TO GO.
- GREAT.
HERE WE GO.
WHAT THE HELL
JUST HAPPENED IN THERE.?
- RELAX.
THEY GOT NOTHING ON YOU.
THEY'RE BLUFFING.
KITTY'S ALIVE.
I JUST SAW HER IN THE BACK ROOM.
THEY JUST WANTED
TO GET YOU SCARED
SO YOU'D TESTIFY
AGAINST POP-POP.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
YOU JUST TOLD THEM THE TRUTH;
THEY LET US WALK.
I GUESS I OWE YOU
50 BUCKS, HUH?
- YEAH,
I'D SAVE YOUR MONEY.
KITTY'S GOT A LOT OF EVIDENCE,
AND SHE THINKS THAT YOU
TRIED TO KILL HER.
SO YOU'RE PROBABLY GOING TO
NEED A BETTER ATTORNEY.
[horn honks]
- LO SIENTO.
- I HATE BRING
YOUR DAUGHTER TO WORK DAY.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
TOBIAS LOSES HIS SECURITY JOB
TRYING TO SOLVE THE STORE'S
MICE PROBLEM.
[gunshots]
LINDSAY, NOW WITHOUT A JOB,
GOES WITH HER INITIAL INSTINCT.
- MOM, WE'RE GONNA
BE LATE FOR PRACTICE!
narrator:
AND ANNYONG EXACTS HIS REVENGE.
- WHERE IS EVERYBODY?
- HEADS UP, FATTY!
[screams]