- [male narrator] NOW
THE STORY OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT".
- LOW-CARB DIETS
ARE SWEEPING THE NATION,
BUT SOME LOCAL BUSINESSES
ARE BEING LEFT IN THE DUST.
- AND THE LATEST ON IRAQ--
- HEY.
GEORGE MICHAEL, THEY'RE GONNA
SHOW THAT INTERVIEW YOU DID.
WE'RE GONNA WATCH IT
ON THURSDAY, OKAY?
I'LL MAKE SOME POPCORN.
- POPCORN, REALLY? COOL.
YEAH, THE HELL
WITH ATKINS, HUH?
- OH, YEAH.
OH, WHY BLOW IT NOW?
I'LL FRY UP SOME BACON.
- UH, DAD.
- BUDDY, YOU GOTTA
TAKE IT EASY, OKAY?
I'M SHOWING THIS
AS A MODEL AGAIN.
I DON'T WANT PEOPLE TO THINK
WE'VE GOT SHODDY WORKMANSHIP.
THAT MIGHT NOT
HAVE BEEN YOUR FAULT.
- I KNOW.
NOTHING WORKS IN THIS HOUSE.
- TELL ME ABOUT IT.
- IS THAT A SHOT AT ME?
- PROBABLY.
- BECAUSE FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
I GOT A JOB.
- REALLY? WHAT KIND OF JOB?
- BEADS.
- BEES?
- BEADS?
- GOB'S NOT ON BOARD.
- BEADS ARE VERY BIG RIGHT NOW.
UH, ANKLETS,
NECKLACES, YOU NAME IT.
- BRACELETS?
- BUT I'LL NEED
SOME START-UP MONEY.
- I'M IN.
BUT WE'RE GONNA NEED A LOT.
BEADS AREN'T CHEAP.
ARE BEADS CHEAP?
- GOB, SHOULDN'T YOU BE IN BED?
- WELL, WE GOT A MEETING
WITH DAD'S ATTORNEY TODAY.
HE'S GONNA WANT ME TO
TAKE A LIE-DETECTOR TEST
TO USE AS EVIDENCE
IN DAD'S TRIAL, BUT, UH,
I DON'T WANT TO.
WHAT IF THEY
ASK ABOUT A MAGIC TRICK?
I JUST--I CAN'T RISK IT.
- THEY'RE NOT GONNA
ASK YOU ANYTHING.
THEY WANT ME TO
TAKE THE POLYGRAPH TEST.
- BUT I'M THE OLDEST.
THE MATRIARCH, IF YOU WILL.
- SURE. I WILL.
LISTEN, I HAVE TO DO
THIS TO HELP OUT DAD,
AND YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT OUR BUSINESS.
- AND GOB, I'M NOT
LOOKING FOR A PARTNER.
AND, BELIEVE ME,
IF I WAS, IT WOULD NOT BE YOU.
- OH.
GOOD.
WELL, I'LL START
MY OWN BUSINESS.
HOW HARD CAN IT BE?
Z-Z-Z-Z-Z!
BZ-Z-Z-Z-Z-Z!
WE'LL SEE
WHO BRINGS IN MORE HONEY.
[buzzing]
- HE'S THINKING
ABOUT BEES AGAIN.
- OH.
- LINDSEY, I'M NOT JUST GONNA
CUT YOU A CHECK
SO YOU CAN THROW IT AWAY ON
ANOTHER FAILED BUSINESS, OKAY?
- HEY, "MOMMY, WHAT WILL
I LOOK LIKE?"
SHOULD HAVE WORKED.
- [narrator]
LINDSAY HAD ONCE STARTED
A PHOTO-ENHANCING SERVICE,
WHICH GAVE
NEW PARENTS A GLIMPSE
AT WHAT THEIR INFANTS WOULD
LOOK LIKE IN HALF A CENTURY.
- HEY, YOU PUT
AN UGLY KID IN,
YOU CAN'T BE SURPRISED
WHEN AN UGLY ADULT COMES OUT.
LOOK, I NEED TO BECOME
SELF-RELIANT.
IT'S NOT GONNA LAST
WITH TOBIAS.
HE'S COMPLETELY
OBLIVIOUS.
I MEAN HE'S GOT NO IDEA
HOW I'M FEELING OR THINKING.
- SO THERE'S NO SEX?
- I MEAN, HOW DO YOU
NOT HAVE SEX WITH ME?
- IT IS A STRUGGLE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'LL HELP YOU OUT,
BUT YOU GOTTA WORK.
- GREAT. BEFORE YOU KNOW IT,
I'LL BE IN THE RED.
AND YOU CAN TAKE
THAT TO THE BANK.
- I'M SURE THEY'LL
CONTACT ME FIRST.
- [narrator] AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL GOT A CALL
THAT MADE HIM WISH HE HADN'T
PROMISED HIS SISTER
THE MONEY.
- HELLO.
KITTY?
- [narrator] AND LATER,
THE FAMILY WAITED FOR MICHAEL
AT THE PRISON MEETING ROOM.
- HOW DO YOU MAKE MONEY FROM IT?
- I DON'T KNOW.
HONEY?
OR JUST AS GIFTS.
- WHO'D WANT A BEE AS A GIFT?
- [narrator] WHILE BUSTER AND
ANNYONG WAITED JUST OUTSIDE.
- COME ON.
JUST LET ME HAVE ONE BITE.
- NO.
MOTHER SAID NO CARBOHYDRATE
FOR YOU IF YOU EVER
GONNA GET GIRLFRIEND
THAT'S NOT OLD LADY.
- AT LEAST
I CAN GET A GIRLFRIEND.
- I CAN GET A GIRLFRIEND
BEFORE YOU.
- OH, WE'LL SEE ABOUT THAT.
- HEY, WHY AREN'T YOU IN THERE?
- OH, I WAS JUST
KEEPING ANNYONG COMPANY.
GIVE ME THAT BAGEL,
YOU LITTLE [bleep].
GIVE IT TO ME!
[bleep]
- WHOA, OUR STAR WITNESS.
COME HERE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
DON'T GET
TOO CLOSE TO ME,
'CAUSE I'VE GOT AN ITCH
YOU CAN'T BELIEVE.
I THINK SOMETHING
LAID EGGS ON ME.
- THANKS FOR THE HEADS-UP.
- THAT'S OKAY.
WE'VE GOT YOUR POLYGRAPH
SET FOR TOMORROW.
- ABOUT THAT--
- I'LL TELL THEM, MICHAEL.
I WON'T DO IT.
I'M AFRAID OF WHAT I MIGHT KNOW.
- YOU?
NO ONE WANTS YOU.
DOES ANYONE WANT HIM, HARRY?
- WHO WOULD WANT HIM?
- THEY DON'T WANT YOU.
- GOOD.
- I MIGHT NOT BE
THE BEST WITNESS EITHER.
I GOT A PHONE CALL
FROM KITTY THIS MORNING.
- YOUR SECRETARY?
- MY SECRETARY.
- SHE SAYS THAT SHE'S GOT
SOME EVIDENCE,
AND SHE'S THREATENING
TO BRING DOWN THE COMPANY
UNLESS WE MEET HER DEMANDS.
- OH, THAT IS JUST GREAT.
AND NOW I'M EXPECTED
TO CLIMB BACK ON TOP OF KITTY
AND DO MY THING AGAIN.
I MEAN, THIS FAMILY
RUNS INTO PROBLEMS,
IT'S, "OH, LET'S HAVE GOB
[bleep] OUR WAY OUT OF IT."
- WHAT IS THE MATTER WITH YOU?
- COME ON. IT'S ME THAT
SHE WANTS TO MEET WITH, GOB.
- OH.
GOOD.
- NOW, WHAT DOES SHE HAVE, DAD?
I NEED TO KNOW.
- NO, YOU CAN'T KNOW.
WE GOT TO KEEP YOU NICE
AND CLEAN, MICHAEL.
ESPECIALLY IF YOU'RE GOING
TO TAKE THAT LIE DETECTOR TEST.
- HE IS ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
- FIND OUT WHAT KITTY WANTS
AND JUST GIVE IT TO HER,
BUT DON'T FIND
OUT WHAT SHE KNOWS.
MICHAEL, YOU CAN
SAVE THIS BUSINESS.
YOU ARE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN DO IT.
- YEAH, BESIDES ME, RIGHT?
BUT I KIND OF GOT MY HANDS
FULL WITH THESE BABIES.
- HE'S GOT BEES!
- NO BEES!
- GET IT!
[jar rolling]
- THEY DON'T ALLOW YOU
TO HAVE BEES IN HERE.
- [narrator] AND BUSINESS WAS
SLOW AT THE BANANA STAND
WHEN GEORGE MICHAEL
MADE A NEW FRIEND.
- HI.
- ARE BANANAS
HIGH IN CARBOHYDRATES
- OH, YOU'RE ON ATKINS TOO?
UH, YEAH.
ACTUALLY, THAT'S, UM--
THAT'S WHY
I'M GONNA BE ON TV.
- YOU ARE?
- I WAS INTERVIEWED FOR
HINDSIGHT, WITH JOHN BEARD.
I, UH,
I GAVE THEM A JOKE,
BUT, I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW
IF THEY'RE GONNA USE IT.
YOU KNOW,
THANKS TO THIS DIET CRAZE,
THE LAST TIME
WE HAD A CUSTOMER,
THE BANANA
STAND WAS STILL GREEN.
- LOSE IT.
NO, LOSE THE WHOLE KID.
WE'LL JUST GO
WITH THE IRAQ PIECE.
- THAT'S SO COOL.
- I GUESS.
- YOU WANNA WATCH
OVER AT MY HOUSE?
- YEAH, I--I GUESS.
- [narrator] AND MICHAEL
HEADED OFF TO MEET KITTY.
THEIR LAST MEETING
HAD ENDED POORLY.
- SAY GOOD-BYE
TO YOUR COMPANY, MICHAEL.
AND SAY GOOD-BYE TO THESE.
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
- [narrator] SO MICHAEL
WAS UNDERSTANDABLY
ANXIOUS ABOUT THEIR REUNION.
- GUESS I DO GET
TO SEE THEM AGAIN, HUH?
[chuckles]
- CAN WE PLEASE
HAVE ONE CONVERSATION
THAT'S NOT
ABOUT MY RACK, MICHAEL?
- YEAH.
- MAYBE A BETTER
QUESTION WOULD BE,
WHAT EVIDENCE
DO I HAVE AGAINST YOU, BECAUSE--
- NO, NO, NO.
I DON'T--I DON'T WANNA KNOW.
I JUST WANT TO KNOW
WHAT YOU WANT.
- I'D LIKE TO BE IN CHARGE
OF THE BLUTH COMPANY.
- WELL, I WANT
A HAMBURGER AND FRENCH FRIES,
BUT I CAN'T HAVE THE BUN
OR THE POTATOES. GET REAL.
- I DESERVE IT.
YOUR FATHER PROMISED IT TO ME
ON THE DAY
HE WENT TO PRISON.
- SOUNDS LIKE SOMETHING
THAT HE WOULD DO.
- AND IF I CAN'T BE IN CHARGE,
THEN I'M GOING TO HAVE TO
TELL THE ENTIRE WORLD
THAT YOUR FATHER WAS
BUILDING HOUSES OVERSEAS
WITHOUT PAYING--
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
JUST STOP, STOP. STOP.
NO, FINISH.
FINISH.
UM, WITHOUT PAYING WHAT?
TAXES?
- MODEL HOUSES, MICHAEL.
OVERSEAS.
AND HE HID IT--[whispering]
FROM THE U.S. GOVERNMENT.
- THAT'S IT? THAT'S WHAT
MY DAD'S BEEN HIDING?
BACK TAXES?
- AND UNLESS YOU PLAN
ON PAYING THEM,
YOUR DAD'S GONNA BE
IN PRISON FOR A LONG TIME.
- WELL, WE'LL PAY THEM.
FORGET IT.
WE'LL JUST--WE'LL MORTGAGE
THE COMPANY IF WE HAVE TO.
WE FOUND MONEY FOR THOSE.
WE'LL FIND MONEY FOR TAXES.
GOOD TO SEE YA.
- YEAH. IF I WAS IN CHARGE,
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN
MY FIRST MOVE TOO.
- [narrator]
AS MICHAEL RETURNED HOME,
GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS HEADING OUT
TO MEET THE GIRL
FROM THE BANANA STAND.
- GREAT NEWS.
THE BUSINESS IS GONNA BE OKAY.
YEAH, I THOUGHT BANANAS
WOULD BE OKAY ON THE DIET.
- NO, NO. I MEANT, WELL,
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN EATING THOSE,
HAVE YOU?
- NO. NO. NOT AT ALL.
JUST SOME NUTS.
- THOSE ARE FINE.
WHAT I MEANT WAS, I THINK
WE'RE GONNA BE SEEING POP-POP
A LITTLE BIT SOONER
THAN WE THOUGHT.
HUH? DOES THAT SOUND GOOD?
- DO YOU HEAR THAT RATTLE?
- IT IS VERY WORRISOME.
- HEY, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
- GREAT NEWS, MICHAEL.
WE'RE THINKING OF PURCHASING
A BLUTH MODEL HOME.
AND LET'S CHECK THE OVEN.
[clattering]
- WHOA, THAT DOESN'T
INSPIRE CONFIDENCE.
- LINDSAY, THE BEAD BUSINESS
TAKING OFF, IS IT?
- ACTUALLY, I AM
THE BREADWINNER, MICHAEL,
AS IT TURNS OUT.
I WAS WALKING
IN A STRANGE PLACE TODAY.
A PLACE I'D NEVER
SET FOOT IN BEFORE.
- [narrator]
TOBIAS, WALKING DOWN A STREET
HE'D BEEN DOWN
MANY TIMES,
SAW A BOOK HE'D WRITTEN YEARS
EARLIER AS A PSYCHIATRIST.
THE BOOK,
INITIALLY UNSUCCESSFUL,
HAD SUDDENLY CAUGHT FIRE.
ALTHOUGH, STRANGELY,
ONLY IN THE GAY COMMUNITY.
- THE BOOK IS HUGE.
AND I HAVE A BIT OF MONEY
COMING MY WAY AS A RESULT.
SO IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I'M GOING TO GO UPSTAIRS
AND RUN THE SHOWER.
LET ME KNOW IF IT'S TOO LOUD
IN THE KITCHEN.
- OKAY, HONEY.
- SO, YOUR HUSBAND
COMES INTO SOME MONEY,
AND SUDDENLY HE'S
NOT SO OBLIVIOUS ANYMORE, HUH?
- HEY, NOW, THIS IS NOT ME
BEING SHALLOW, MICHAEL.
HE'S WRITTEN A SELF-HELP BOOK
THAT'S HELPING PEOPLE.
THAT DOES TAKE SOME INSIGHT.
- LISTEN, THIS BETTER NOT MEAN
YOU'RE BLOWING OFF
THE BEAD STORE.
- WELL, UH, SEEING AS THOUGH
YOU BROUGHT IT UP,
MAYBE WE SHOULD GET OUT
OF THIS INVESTMENT.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY,
MICHAEL, BEADS?
- I KNEW YOU'D DO THIS.
YOU WORK FOR THREE SECONDS,
AND YOU FIND SOMETHING
THAT'S EASIER
AND THEN YOU JUST GRAB IT.
IT'S "DIP-A-PET"
ALL OVER AGAIN.
- [narrator]
LINDSAY ALSO HAD A BRIEF FORAY
INTO WHAT
SHE HAD THEN HOPED...
- COME BACK HERE!
- WOULD BE THE BURGEONING FAD
OF CUSTOM PET COLORING.
- WELL, THAT WOULD'VE WORKED
IF YOU'D SPRUNG
FOR A BIGGER SINK.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
OUR SHOW'S ABOUT TO START.
- HE WENT OUT ON HIS DATE.
- A DATE?
BUT WE HAD PLANS
TO--A DATE WITH WHO?
- SOME GIRL.
I MEAN, SHE BARELY HAS A FACE.
YOU COULDN'T PICK HER OUT
OF A LINEUP OF ONE.
- BUT FIRST,
THE PALACES OF IRAQ.
TRISHA, TELL US ABOUT
THESE NEW MINI-PALACES
OF SADDAM'S YOU'VE DISCOVERED.
- OUR TROOPS HAVE BEEN LIVING
HERE FOR THE LAST FEW DAYS,
AND, AS YOU CAN TELL, THEY'VE
MADE THEMSELVES RIGHT AT HOME.
NOW, A LOT OF THIS DAMAGE
IS JUST DUE
TO SHODDY WORKMANSHIP,
BUT THE REAL SURPRISE HERE
IS THAT THESE HOMES
APPEAR TO BE AMERICAN-BUILT
TO BEGIN WITH.
- THERE HAVE BEEN SANCTIONS
AGAINST DOING BUSINESS
WITH HUSSEIN'S REGIME
SINCE THE EARLY '90S,
SO WHO BUILT THEM?
- DOES THAT LOOK A LITTLE LIKE
OUR KITCHEN ISLAND?
- WELL, WHOEVER IT IS,
THEY'RE IN A WORLD OF TROUBLE.
- [narrator]
AND MICHAEL REALIZED
THAT HIS FATHER'S CRIMES MIGHT
BE BIGGER THAN HE THOUGHT.
- THERE'S A GOOD CHANCE
I MAY HAVE COMMITTED
SOME LIGHT TREASON.
- THIS MIGHT EVEN BE
CONSIDERED LIGHT TREASON.
- OH, MY GOD.
[glass shattering]
- [narrator]
MICHAEL HAD JUST FOUND OUT
HIS FATHER MIGHT HAVE COMMITTED
SOME LIGHT TREASON
BY BUILDING MODEL HOMES IN IRAQ.
AND HE TRIED TO GET AHOLD
OF KITTY,
WHO HE KNEW
HAD THE EVIDENCE.
UNFORTUNATELY, KITTY WAS
MEETING WITH GOB AT THE TIME.
- WHAT ABOUT HASH BROWNS?
- NO, BECAUSE HASH BROWNS
ARE POTATOES.
- SO YOU REALLY CAN'T
EAT ANYTHING ON THIS DIET.
WOW. WONDER HOW THIS IS GONNA
AFFECT MY HONEY BUSINESS?
- GOB, I HAVE SEEN
YOU GET PASSED OVER
TIME AND TIME
AGAIN BY YOUR FAMILY.
YOU DON'T DESERVE THAT.
YOU'RE SMARTER THAN THEM.
- WHAT ABOUT MACARONI?
LET ME FINISH...
SALAD?
- GOB, THIS IS YOUR TIME.
WITH MY HELP,
KNOWING WHAT I KNOW,
WE COULD TAKE OVER
THE BLUTH COMPANY TOGETHER.
- WOW.
THIS IS A SIDE OF YOU
I'D NEVER NOTICED BEFORE.
HAVE THEY
ALWAYS BEEN THAT BIG?
- [narrator] AND THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL WENT TO HIS MOTHER'S.
- I SAW AN EXPOSÉ
ON THE IRAQ PALACES LAST NIGHT,
AND I COULD HAVE SWORN
THAT ONE OF THEM
WAS THE SEA WIND UNIT.
- THAT'S FUNNY.
I ALWAYS PICTURED IRAQ
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DESERT.
- DAD SOLD HOUSES
TO THE IRAQIS, DIDN'T HE?
AND THIS IS
WHAT YOU KEPT FROM ME
SO I COULD TAKE
THE POLYGRAPH TEST.
TELL ME THE TRUTH, OKAY?
'CAUSE THERE'S BEEN A LOT
OF LYING IN THIS FAMILY.
- AND A LOT OF LOVE.
- MORE LIES.
- LOOK, I NEVER KNEW
ABOUT ANYTHING,
BUT I HAD MY SUSPICIONS.
HE NEVER TOLD ME
WHERE HE WAS GOING,
BUT HE USED TO COME BACK
FROM THOSE BUSINESS TRIPS
REEKING OF LAMB.
AND PEOPLE WOULD SEND FIGS,
NOT EVEN AT CHRISTMAS,
IN THE MIDDLE OF OCTOBER.
OH, AND ONCE,
SOMEONE SENT HIM A TOE,
AND HE WENT WHITE AS A SHEET.
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT,
MICHAEL.
- ZERO HOUR, MICHAEL.
IT'S THE END OF THE LINE.
I'M THE FIRST BORN.
SICK OF PLAYING SECOND FIDDLE.
ALWAYS THIRD IN LINE
FOR EVERYTHING.
TIRED OF FINISHING FOURTH.
BEING THE FIFTH WHEEL.
THERE ARE SIX THINGS
I'M MAD ABOUT.
AND I'M TAKING OVER.
- YOU WANT TO BE IN CHARGE?
- YEAH.
- YOU WANT TO DEAL WITH
WHAT I DEAL WITH.
A SISTER WHO TAKES YOUR MONEY
AND THROWS IT AWAY;
A MOTHER WHO YOU CAN'T TRUST;
A COMPANY WHOSE FOUNDER
MAY BE ON TRIAL FOR TREASON.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
- WHAT KIND OF VACATION TIME
DOES IT OFFER?
- YEAH.
- [narrator] GOB REALIZED
THAT THE POWER PLAY
HE PROMISED
TO MAKE WITH KITTY
HAD PERHAPS COME AT A BAD TIME.
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
- [narrator] AND TOBIAS WAS
HAVING HIS FIRST BOOK READING.
- AND, FOR THE EASE
OF THE READER,
I HAVE CHANGED ALL
THE GENDER-RELATED PRONOUNS:
"HE," "SHE,"
TO THE MASCULINE "HE."
"THE MAN INSIDE ME.
FOR LINDSAY, MY ROCK.
I COULD NOT HAVE
DONE THIS WITHOUT HIM."
- [narrator] AND LINDSAY ARRIVED
TO SUPPORT HER HUSBAND.
"FOR THERE IS
A MAN INSIDE ME,
AND ONLY WHEN
HE'S FINALLY OUT
CAN I WALK FREE OF PAIN."
- THIS BOOK IS GONNA
SELL, LIKE, A BILLION COPIES.
- LINDSAY
OH, I'M SO GLAD YOU CAME.
I WAS HOPING FOR MORE WOMEN.
PERHAPS I SHOULDN'T
HAVE JUST USED "HE."
I THINK THAT WAS A MISTAKE.
- [narrator] AND LINDSAY
REALIZED THAT TOBIAS
WAS JUST AS OBLIVIOUS
AS SHE'D ALWAYS THOUGHT.
- TOBIAS, I DON'T THINK THIS
RELATIONSHIP IS GONNA WORK.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WE'VE HAD SOME GREAT TIMES.
WE'VE GOT NOTHING LEFT, TOBIAS.
- [narrator] AND MICHAEL WENT
TO CONFRONT HIS FATHER.
- YOU'RE BUILDING
HOUSES IN IRAQ?
I MEAN, DO YOU KNOW
HOW THEY PUNISH TREASON?
- FIRST TIME.
- I'VE NEVER
HEARD OF A SECOND.
- OH, I'VE GOT
THE WORST [bleep] ATTORNEYS.
THIS IS WHY I DIDN'T WANT
TO GET YOU INVOLVED.
BUT WE CAN FIX THIS.
WHAT ARE KITTY'S DEMANDS?
WHAT DOES SHE WANT?
- SHE WANTS MY JOB.
SUDDENLY EVERYBODY WANTS MY JOB,
AND I SHOULD'VE
GIVEN IT TO HER.
- YOU MEAN,
YOU DIDN'T? MICHAEL!
SHE HAS THE EVIDENCE
OF WHAT WE DID OVER THERE.
- NO, ALL SHE THINKS IT IS
IS UNPAID TAXES.
- YEAH. WHAT IF SHE
GIVES IT TO SOMEONE
WHO'S EVEN
MODERATELY INTELLIGENT?
- [narrator]
IN FACT, KITTY HAD GONE
TO SOMEONE
MODERATELY INTELLIGENT
IN HER CONTINUING QUEST
FOR CONTROL
OF THE BLUTH COMPANY.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU CALLED ME FOR A DATE.
- YOU DIDN'T
TELL ANYONE, DID YOU?
- ARE YOU KIDDING?
I DON'T NEED TO BRAG
THAT SOME PEOPLE
HAVEN'T EVEN BEEN ON A DATE.
- DAY NOT OVER YET, FATTY.
- YOU WEREN'T THINKING CLEARLY.
I MEAN, NONE OF US ARE.
WE NEED BREAD.
- IF THIS INFORMATION
WAS SO DAMAGING,
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST SHRED IT?
- WELL, SADDAM OWED US MONEY.
- YOU DIDN'T REALIZE
THAT HE WOULDN'T PAY?
- YOUR MOM HAD
A GOOD FEELING ABOUT HIM.
- SO MOM KNEW
THIS ENTIRE TIME,
AND SHE JUST LIED TO MY FACE
FOR MONTHS AND MONTHS?
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING, DAD.
THIS IS--THIS IS YOUR PROBLEM.
OKAY? NOT MINE.
- YEAH, WELL, MAYBE IT
WOULDN'T BE MY PROBLEM
IF YOU DID WHAT I ASKED
FOR ONCE IN YOUR DAMN LIFE
AND YOU GAVE KITTY
WHAT I ASKED YOU TO.
- ONCE IN MY DAMN LIFE?
ALL I'VE EVER DONE
MY ENTIRE LIFE
IS DO EXACTLY WHAT YOU
TOLD ME TO, ALL RIGHT?
I'VE DONE EVERYTHING
FOR THIS FAMILY, POP.
NOT ANYMORE.
KITTY CAN HAVE MY JOB.
AND YOU CAN TAKE YOUR OWN
POLYGRAPH TEST, 'CAUSE I'M DONE.
I'M DONE WITH YOU,
AND I'M DONE WITH THE BUSINESS.
- GREAT.
I'M GONNA GET
A LETHAL INJECTION
BECAUSE MY SON
WON'T EAT A POTATO.
- [narrator] GEORGE SENIOR,
IN A SURPRISE MOVE
VOLUNTEERED TO TAKE
THE POLYGRAPH.
- SO DID YOU SWIPE THE SEDATIVE
FROM THE INFIRMARY?
- NO.
- TO LOWER YOUR HEART RATE?
- NO. IT'S OKAY.
I WANT TO DO THIS,
BECAUSE I WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW I
NEVER WILLFULLY DECEIVED ANYONE.
MISTAKES WERE MADE,
BUT I NEVER INTENDED
TO HURT ANYONE.
I WAS TRYING TO
SUPPORT MY FAMILY.
- HE DOESN'T APPEAR
TO BE ON A SEDATIVE.
- BUT I CAN SEE CLEARLY NOW.
SITTING IN THIS CHAIR,
STRAPPED TO THIS MACHINE,
I CAN SEE THAT MY LIFE
HAS BECOME A FAILURE!
I'VE LET PEOPLE DOWN,
LET MYSELF DOWN.
BUT I LOVE MY COUNTRY!
I LOVE IT HERE!
YOU CAN SHOP.
I LOVE MY--CAN'T BREATHE.
I CAN'T BREATHE.
- WAIT! WAIT!
ARE YOU GUILTY? YES OR NO?
- I THINK HE'S HAVING
A HEART ATTACK.
- THAT WAS NOT A NOD.
- NO. THAT WAS NOT A NOD.
- CALL AN AMBULANCE!
- OH, MY GOD.
[siren wailing]
- OH, HOW IS HE?
- STABLE.
BUT THEY DON'T KNOW
IF HE'S DUE FOR ANOTHER ONE.
IT'S HIS OWN FAULT.
WHAT KIND OF DIET IS THIS?
IT'S TOO MUCH MEAT.
I WANT ALL OF YOU
OFF THIS IMMEDIATELY.
EXCEPT YOU.
- TOBIAS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU CAME.
- OH, COME ON, LINDSAY.
THIS IS MY FAMILY.
- [narrator]
AND LINDSAY REALIZED
THAT PERHAPS THEY DID HAVE
SOMETHING LEFT.
A REAL CONNECTION.
- ALSO, DALE, ONE OF
THE GENTLEMEN FROM MY READING,
IS A NURSE HERE, SO WE WERE ABLE
TO PARK RIGHT OUT FRONT.
- OH, BARRY.
DID YOU TALK TO A DOCTOR?
- I DID. I HAVE POISON OAK.
DO YOU BELIEVE IT?
WHERE THE HELL DID I GET THAT?
[dog barks]
- SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT GEORGE.
- NO, HE'S THE SAME.
LOOK, I GUESS
WE SHOULD DECIDE
ON WHO'S GONNA SPEAK
FOR THE FAMILY.
I WOULD, BUT I HAVE
LAKER TICKETS.
[dog barks]
- [narrator]
BUSTER KNEW THIS WAS HIS CHANCE
TO PUT KITTY'S
COUP D'ETAT IN ACTION.
HE WONDERED IF HE WAS UP FOR IT.
- SOMEONE MIGHT HAVE TO SIGN
THE "DO NOT RESUSCITATE" FORM.
AND HE DECIDED HE WASN'T.
- I NEED TO MAKE
A TELEPHONE CALL.
GET OUT OF SOMETHING.
- I'M IN CHARGE NOW.
I SPEAK FOR THIS FAMILY.
I MEAN, I COULD,
IF YOU WANTED ME TO.
I'D RATHER NOT, OBVIOUSLY.
DON'T KNOW WHAT I'D SAY.
I MEAN, WHY DO I
HAVE TO BE THE ONE?
I DON'T NEED THIS.
WHY DOES THIS HAVE TO BECOME
MY PROBLEM?
NO. I'M OUT.
FORGET IT.
FIND SOMEBODY ELSE.
I'M SICK OF IT.
I'M SICK OF DOING EVERYTHING
FOR THIS FAMILY.
- WHERE IS MICHAEL?
- [scoffs] TYPICAL.
- DID SOMEBODY CALL HIM?
- [narrator]
IN FACT, THEY HADN'T.
AND AT THAT MOMENT,
HE WAS DETERMINED
TO FINALLY GET AS FAR AWAY
FROM HIS FAMILY AS POSSIBLE.
- HEY, PAL.
PACK YOUR BAGS.
- WHERE ARE WE GOIN'?
- ANYWHERE.
JOSHUA TREE, SPACE CAMP,
THE BASEBALL HALL OF FAME.
EVERYTHING YOU AND I
HAVE ALWAYS WANTED TO DO
BUT HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO BECAUSE
OF THIS RIDICULOUS FAMILY.
- WE'RE JUST GONNA GO?
- YEAH.
AND I DON'T KNOW
IF WE'RE EVEN GONNA COME BACK.
THERE'S NOTHING KEEPING US HERE.
- WELL, DAD,
I LIKE IT HERE.
- WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON
WITH YOU LATELY?
I WANTED TO WATCH "HINDSIGHT",
AND YOU WEREN'T THERE.
I WANT TO PACK UP
AND DESERT THE FAMILY,
AND YOU DON'T WANT TO.
IS IT THIS NEW GIRLFRIEND?
- NO, IT--
IT'S BECAUSE OF THE FAMILY.
I LIKE THE FAMILY.
I MEAN, IF WE LEAVE, WHO'S GONNA
TAKE CARE OF THESE PEOPLE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
THE STATE OR THE POLICE.
MAYBE THE MAGICIANS' ALLIANCE
WILL PICK UP SOME SLACK.
[phone ringing]
HEY. THAT'S GONNA BE THEM,
AND THEY'RE
GONNA WANT SOMETHING.
WE'RE NOT ANSWERING THAT.
[ringing continues]
- HELLO.
- WHERE'S GEORGE MICHAEL?
- EXACTLY. WHERE IS HE?
EVER SINCE HE'S BEEN DATING
THIS ANNIE MCNO-FACE,
HE'S BEEN BLOWING ME OFF.
- OH, HEY. WHERE'S POP-POP?
- ROOM 212.
- [narrator]
AND THAT'S WHEN MAEBY DECIDED
THAT PERHAPS
SHE COULD USE HER UNCLE
TO MAKE HER COUSIN JEALOUS.
- HEY, DAD. WAIT UP.
- THAT WAS A WASTE OF TIME.
- [groaning]
- HOW'S HE DOIN'?
- HE'S HANGING IN THERE.
HE KEEPS TRYING TO GET
THIS I.V. OUT OF HIS ARM.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY.
IT'S JUST GLUCOSE.
- WE'RE ALL TRYING
TO STAY AWAY FROM SUGAR.
- HE'S GONNA BE OKAY, RIGHT?
- ABSOLUTELY.
ABSOLUTELY. YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I'LL HANDLE THIS ONE, MICHAEL.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
IT'LL TAKE A LOT MORE
THAN A HEART ATTACK
TO KILL THAT OLD BEAR.
OLD BEAR!
HE LIKES THE HONEY.
HE NEVER GOT A CHANCE
TO SEE MY BEE BUSINESS TAKE OFF.
- HEY, COME ON, NOW.
DAD'S GONNA BE AROUND
ANOTHER 30 YEARS, GOB.
YOUR BUSINESS, UH, MIGHT NOT.
- YOU'RE A GOOD BROTHER,
MICHAEL.
HEART ATTACK
NEVER STOP OLD BIG BEAR.
- I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
WE WERE CALLING HIM BIG BEAR.
- WE NEVER HAD A CHANCE TO!
- HEY, HEY. COME ON, GOB.
EVERYBODY, I'M VERY SORRY, OKAY?
I FEEL AWFUL.
I SHOULD HAVE BEEN HERE.
I WAS THE ONE THAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO TAKE THAT POLYGRAPH TEST,
AND THEN I JUST TURNED ON HIM,
AND THEN THIS HAPPENED,
BUT NEVER AGAIN, OKAY?
I WILL NEVER, EVER LEAVE
THIS FAMILY, NO MATTER WHAT.
- YOU SHOULD'VE BEEN HERE.
- I FEEL LIKE I COVERED THAT.
- WELL, YOU DIDN'T SAY IT.
- I FEEL AWFUL.
I SHOULD HAVE BEEN HERE.
MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
MAYBE I DIDN'T SAY IT.
I SHOULD HAVE BEEN HERE.
- EXCUSE ME, MR. BLUTH.
- HMM?
- WE LOST HIM.
[all gasping]
HE JUST, UH,
GOT AWAY FROM US. I'M SORRY.
- UH, CAN WE GO IN THERE?
- IF YOU WANT. NOT A LOT TO SEE.
- MAYBE NOT FOR YOU, BUT FOR US.
- [narrator] AND THAT'S WHEN
THE FAMILY REALIZED
THAT GEORGE SR. WASN'T DEAD
BUT WAS FLEEING THE COUNTRY
THAT HE LOVED SO VERY MUCH.
- PACK YOUR BAGS.
- [narrator] ON THE NEXT SEASON
OF "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT"
THE FAMILY GRAPPLES WITH
THE NEWS THEY HAD JUST HEARD.
- WHY WOULD A DOCTOR SAY
HE'S "GONE"
WHEN HE MEANS HE'S ESCAPED?
- GOD, I'VE MISSED BREAD. MMM.
- WOULDN'T YOU SAY,
"HE LEFT OUT THE WINDOW"
OR, "THE ROOM'S EMPTY."
- [narrator] MAEBY'S LIFE GETS
A LITTLE MORE COMPLICATED.
- I MEAN, IT'S SO OBVIOUS.
HE GAVE HIMSELF THE SHOT
TO MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
A HEART ATTACK.
HOW COULD
THEY NOT SEE THAT?
- MAYBE WE SHOULD KISS AGAIN
TO TEACH THEM A LESSON
ABOUT OBVIOUS.
- [narrator] AND KITTY
HELPS GEORGE SENIOR ESCAPE.