[narrator]
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
[narrator]
THIS IS MICHAEL BLUTH.
RIGHT NOW HE'S
TAKING HIS SON, GEORGE MICHAEL,
TO START A NEW LIFE IN ARIZONA.
- PHOENIX, ARIZONA, HUH?
THIS IS IT, BOY.
WE ARE FREE.
WE'RE GONNA FOLLOW
OUR DREAMS, YOU KNOW?
AND THE BEST PART OF IT?
NOT WORKIN'
FOR THE FAMILY ANYMORE.
- YEAH, BUT DON'T-- DON'T YOU
ALWAYS SAY "FAMILY FIRST"?
- YES, I DO.
BUT THAT IS
NOT A FAMILY, OKAY?
THEY'RE A BUNCH
OF GREEDY, SELFISH PEOPLE
WHO HAVE OUR NOSE.
AND AUNT LINDSAY.
- SHE'S NOT MY REAL AUNT?
- NOT A REAL NOSE.
GOT A PICTURE OF HER WHEN
SHE'S 14 IN A SWIMMING CAP.
SHE LOOKS LIKE A FALCON.
SPENT AN ENTIRE YEAR LIVING
IN THAT STUPID MODEL HOME
WITH THOSE PEOPLE,
AND ALL THEY DID
WAS LIE TO US.
[narrator]
THE MOST RECENT LIE WAS
MICHAEL'S FATHER HAD HAD
A HEART ATTACK WHILE IN PRISON.
- WE LOST HIM.
[sobbing]
[narrator]
WHAT THE DOCTOR MEANT TO SAY
WAS THAT GEORGE SR. HAD ESCAPED,
A FEAT HE'D ACCOMPLISHED
BY USING THE FAMILY'S PORTABLE
STAIRWAY VEHICLE.
- I'D LOVE TO SEE THE LOOK
ON THEIR FACES RIGHT NOW.
[chuckles]
"WHERE'D HE GO?"
- OR THEY-- THEY THINK WE'RE
JUST HEADED HOME.
ACTUALLY, YOU KNOW,
THAT'S KIND OF WHAT I THOUGHT...
UNTIL I HEARD ABOUT
ALL THAT PHOENIX STUFF.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS CONCERNED THAT THE
FULL IMPACT OF HIS DEPARTURE..
MIGHT HAVE BEEN LOST
ON HIS FAMILY.
[phone beeping]
- HELLO. WHO IS THIS?
- YES, THIS IS DR. BLUMEN.
I'M CALLING
REGARDING MICHAEL BLUTH.
- MICHAEL! PHONE!
[beeps]
- THEY THINK
WE'RE STILL THERE.
WE'RE GOIN' BACK.
[phone line beeping]
HEY, MOM. ANY MESSAGES?
- NONE.
[recorded voice,
indistinct]
- NO, THERE WAS A MESSAGE.
IT WAS ABOUT MY HEALTH,
BUT IT DOESN'T MATTER.
MY SON AND I--
[horn blasts]
- BUSTER, WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH MOTHER'S RAPE HORN?
YES, I HAVE A RAPE HORN,
MICHAEL, BECAUSE YOU
TOOK AWAY MY MACE.
- YEAH, LIKE ANYONE
WOULD WANT TO "R" HER.
- THIS IS WHAT I'M TALKING
ABOUT, MICHAEL.
NOW THAT YOUR FATHER HAS
DESERTED US, BUSTER'S BECOME
IMPOSSIBLE TO CONTROL.
SUDDENLY HE'S
TOO MUCH OF A BIG SHOT
TO BRUSH MOTHER'S HAIR.
- WELL, I'M NOT HE--
I'M NOT HELPING YOU
WITH BUSTER ANYMORE.
I'M NOT HELPING ANYONE
WITH ANYTHING.
I CAME HERE TO TELL YOU
THAT MY SON AND I--
[blender whirring]
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL, MEANWHILE, WAS
APPROACHED BY HIS COUSIN MAEBY.
- SO, YOU'RE REALLY
LEAVIN', HUH?
HAVE YOU TOLD
YOUR GIRLFRIEND, BLAND?
I MEAN, ANN.
- SHE'S NOT MY GIRLFRIEND,
AND SHE'S NOT BLAND.
- REALLY?
BECAUSE, I MEAN,
UNDER HER SCHOOL PICTURE
IT SAID "NOT PICTURED."
- OKAY, THEY PRINTED A
RETRACTION
IN THE SPRING SUPPLEMENT.
AND, YEAH, SHE WAS REALLY
LOOKIN' FORWARD TO SEEING ME
IN MY UNCLE SAM OUTFIT...
IN THAT GET OUT THE VOTE
ASSEMBLY TOMORROW.
- WASN'T THAT SUPPOSED TO BE
BEFORE THE ELECTION?
- THEY HAD TO POSTPONE IT WHEN
THAT FOREIGN EXCHANGE STUDENT
PARKED TOO CLOSE TO THE GYM.
- I DO IT.
I PLAY UNCLE SAM.
BETTER THAN PART I HAVE NOW--
GUY WHO ORDERS STRIKE
ON PEARL HARBOR.
- I DON'T KNOW WHY
YOU'RE NOT TAKING THIS
"I'M OUT OF HERE" SERIOUSLY,
BUT I AM OUT OF HERE,
SERIOUSLY.
- LET'S FACE IT, MICHAEL.
YOU'VE MADE THIS THREAT BEFORE.
- TELL ME. WHEN?
- THAT'S IT.
I'M OUT OF HERE.
TA-DA!
- [man on radio]
WE GOT THE ATTACKING
ANIMAL DOWN.
- I'M OUT OF THIS FAMILY,
SERIOUSLY.
THIS TIME WE'RE GONNA BE
SO FAR AWAY, YOU'LL NEVER
BE ABLE TO FIND US.
- WE'RE GOIN' TO PHOENIX.
- DON'T TELL 'EM WHERE.
- I-I JUST THOUGHT--
- IT DOESN'T MATTER WHY.
- MICHAEL, MAYBE THE REASON
WHY YOU ALWAYS COME BACK...
IS BECAUSE YOU NEED US
MORE THAN WE NEED YOU.
- [scoffs]
OH, THAT'S RICH.
HUH. I NEED YOU.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
MOM, YOU'RE ALWAYS ASKING ME
TO HELP YOU LOOK AFTER BUSTER.
YOU CAN FIND SOMEBODY ELSE.
I HOPE SHE DOESN'T KILL YOU.
- I'LL KILL HER FIRST.
- AND GOOD LUCK TRYING TO
FIND SOMEONE ELSE TO RUN
THE BUSINESS, BY THE WAY.
GOB, INSTEAD OF
ALWAYS COMING TO ME
ASKING ME FOR MONEY,
SAYING,
"I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE,"
YOU CAN BAIL YOURSELF OUT
NEXT TIME.
- I'VE NEVER ADMITTED
TO A MISTAKE.
WHAT WOULD I
HAVE MADE A MISTAKE ABOUT?
- LINDSAY, INSTEAD OF SLEEPING
IN TWIN BEDS, YOU AND YOUR
HUSBAND TAKE THE MASTER BEDROOM.
IT'S NOT LIKE
YOU'VE NEVER COME TO ME
WITH YOUR MARITAL PROBLEMS,
SAYING,
"OH, HELP ME, MICHAEL.
I THINK MY HUSBAND MIGHT BE A--"
[horn blasts]
- OHH!
[laughing]
WELL-- IT'S--
[groans]
- HERE WE GO.
[narrator]
AND SO, ONCE AGAIN,
THE GUYS WERE ON THEIR WAY TO
PHOENIX, NEVER TO LOOK BACK.
- [low voice]
IT'S JUST THE LAB CALLING.
WE'LL GIVE HIM THE BAD NEWS
IN PHOENIX.
THEY KNOW WE'RE GONE.
- GREAT.
YOU DID SAY PHOENIX AGAIN,
BUT WHAT DO WE CARE?
- SORRY.
- NOW, DO YOU WANT TO STEER,
OR ARE YOU TOO OLD TO SIT
ON YOUR POP'S LAP AND DRIVE?
- I THINK I MIGHT BE.
- OKAY.
[siren winding down]
- CAR'S REGISTERED
TO GEORGE BLUTH,
SO WE HAD TO CHECK.
BUT HE'S BEEN CAUGHT,
SO YOU'RE FREE TO GO.
- HE'S BEEN CAUGHT?
[narrator]
MICHAEL KNEW IF HE WENT BACK
TO SEE HIS FATHER,
HE WOULD ONLY END UP
SAYING SOMETHING HURTFUL.
- WE'RE GOIN' BACK.
[narrator]
IN FACT, THE POLICE ONLY THOUGHT
THEY'D ARRESTED GEORGE SR.
- DO YOU HAVE ANY COOKIES
WITH NO PRESERVATIVES?
[narrator]
BUT HAD GOTTEN HIS TWIN
BROTHER, OSCAR, INSTEAD.
- OSCAR! A TALL TEA
FOR OSCAR!
- YEAH!
- OH, GOOD GRIEF.
IT'S OSCAR.
- OH, THANK GOD YOU'VE COME.
[sighs]
[narrator]
LUCILLE HAD A RELATIONSHIP
WITH OSCAR YEARS EARLIER,
WHICH SHE WAS NOT EAGER
TO REKINDLE.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
THE BOY IS HERE.
- OH.
THEY SAID MY FATHER WAS HERE.
- DID THEY?
- LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
- WHAT-WHAT ABOUT OSCAR?
- YES. THEY IMPOUNDED MY, UH--
MY HUMBLE TRAILER.
- YOU'LL STAY WITH US.
- NO, HE WON'T.
- YOU'RE THE ONE WHO SAYS
I NEED A FATHER FIGURE.
- YES.
A FATHER FIGURE.
- FINE. BUT YOU'RE NOT
SLEEPING IN MY BED.
- OKAY.
- OKAY. YEAH.
[narrator]
SOON, MICHAEL ARRIVED
TO CLAIM HIS FATHER...
AND WAS MET BY THE FAMILY
ATTORNEY, BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
- HMM.
- NO, I KNOW,
I KNOW, I KNOW.
EVERYBODY SAYS LEAVE IT ALONE,
LEAVE IT ALONE.
DOES THIS LOOK CONTAGIOUS
TO YOU?
HEY, KIDDO.
ALL RIGHT.
IT WASN'T YOUR FATHER.
IT WAS YOUR UNCLE.
I RAN INTO THEM
AS THEY WERE LEAVING.
- THERE HE IS!
- GOT YA!
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
- [grunts] YEAH!
- I ONLY CAME BACK TO TELL HIM
I WAS LEAVING, SO I GUESS
IT'S TIME TO GO, SON.
- WHERE YOU GOING?
- WE CAN'T TELL YOU.
- NO, NO. WE CAN TELL BARRY.
WE'RE GOING TO PHOENIX.
- OH, I WISH YOU
HADN'T HAVE SAID THAT.
AS YOUR LAWYER,
I HAVE TO INFORM YOU
YOU CANNOT LEAVE THE STATE.
WITH YOUR FATHER GONE,
THEY WANT TO HOLD YOU.
- M-ME?
- THEY'RE GOING TO
INDICT YOU TOMORROW.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS COME UP WITH THE BAIL.
TAKE IT OUT OF THE BUSINESS.
- BUT I-- I CAN'T.
I QUIT.
I DON'T WANT TO FOLLOW
IN MY FATHER'S FOOTSTEPS.
- THEN YOU MIGHT WIND UP
ON HIS COT.
OH, MAN, I WISH YOU
HADN'T SAID PHOENIX.
WOW.
[narrator]
MICHAEL HAD JUST FOUND OUT
HE COULDN'T LEAVE THE STATE...
UNLESS HE CAME UP WITH BAIL.
- OKAY, LISTEN.
I'M GONNA GET
THE COMPANY CHECKBOOK
AND DON'T TELL THE FAMILY.
WE CAN'T GIVE THEM
THE SATISFACTION OF TELLING THEM
THAT I NEED MONEY, OKAY?
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT WE
SAY ABOUT THE FAMILY?
- IT'S NOT AUNT LINDSAY'S NOSE.
- YES, BUT NO.
DON'T-- DON'T TELL THEM
THAT WE WERE GOIN' TO--
- WE SAY WE DON'T
NEED THEM. HMM?
- OH. YEAH. OKAY.
THE NEW ONE.
I DIDN'T--
[tv: woman]
IT COMES FROM KNOWING
YOU'RE TONED AND FIT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I'M EXERCISING, MICHAEL.
I SEE YOU FOUND AN EXERCISE
TAPE MADE FOR PEOPLE
AS LAZY AS YOU ARE.
- I DO HAVE A LOVE LIFE.
- TIGHTEN, ONE, TWO, THREE.
- OKAY, THIS IS GOING OFF.
ONE NIGHT IN THE MASTER BEDROOM,
AND YOU GOT YOURSELF
A LOVE LIFE AGAIN?
- WELL, I'LL BE HONEST.
AT FIRST, IT WAS AWKWARD.
[tv: woman]
TOGETHER, TWO, THREE, FOUR.
RELEASE, TWO, THREE, FOUR.
- OH, LINDSAY.
[tv off]
UH, WELL,
THIS IS EXCITING.
- FINALLY WE CAN BE
A NORMAL COUPLE.
- NICE TO BE BACK IN A QUEEN.
IT'S TOO MUCH PRESSURE.
- I CAN'T DO THIS.
[narrator]
SO LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
FINALLY TOOK A HARD
LOOK AT THEIR RELATIONSHIP.
- YOU KNOW, LINDSAY,
AS A THERAPIST, I HAVE ADVISED
A NUMBER OF COUPLES...
TO EXPLORE
AN OPEN RELATIONSHIP...
WHERE-WHERE THE COUPLE REMAINS
EMOTIONALLY COMMITTED,
BUT FREE TO EXPLORE
EXTRAMARITAL ENCOUNTERS.
- DID IT WORK
FOR THOSE PEOPLE?
- NO. IT NEVER DOES.
THESE PEOPLE SOMEHOW
DELUDE THEMSELVES INTO
THINKING IT MIGHT, BUT--
BUT IT MIGHT
WORK FOR US.
- WELL, WE COULD GIVE IT A SHOT.
- GREAT. WE'LL HAMMER OUT
THE DETAILS LATER.
RIGHT NOW WE'VE GOT
A DAUGHTER TO TELL.
MAEBY, WE'RE HAVING
A FAMILY MEETING!
[narrator]
ON HER WAY
TO THE FAMILY MEETING,
- FAMILY MEETING!
[narrator]
LINDSAY HAD
AN UNEXPECTED ENCOUNTER.
- HELLO.
- OH, HI.
GOB TOLD ME TO COME BY.
- WELL, UH,
I DON'T THINK HE'S HERE.
- WELL, TELL HIM
I LIKE WHAT I SEE.
- AND WE PROBABLY WON'T
EVEN ACT ON IT.
WE'RE NOT
GONNA GET A DIVORCE.
IF ANYTHING,
IT'LL BRING MOMMY AND DADDY
CLOSER TOGETHER.
- I MET SOMEONE.
I'VE GOT A DATE.
I'M DATING SOMEONE.
- WELL, LET THE GREAT
EXPERIMENT BEGIN!
- YOU'RE NOT USING
MY MASTER BEDROOM FOR THAT.
- I BELIEVE YOU LEFT.
OR DID YOU REALIZE HOW MUCH
YOU NEED US AFTER ALL?
- ACTUALLY, I CAME BACK
BECAUSE I NEED SOMETHING.
- HMM.
- SOME THINGS.
LIKE THE CHECKBOOK.
WHERE'S THE CORPORATE CHECKBOOK?
- GOB MUST'VE TAKEN IT
TO THE OFFICE.
MOM PUT HIM IN CHARGE.
THAT'S RIGHT, MICHAEL.
HE'S GOT YOUR OLD JOB.
- WELL, I BETTER GET OVER THERE
BEFORE HE BRINGS THE WHOLE
COMPANY DOWN.
- IT'S ONLY BEEN THREE HOURS.
HOW MUCH DAMAGE
COULD HE REALLY DO?
AND RELEASE.
[narrator]
IN THREE HOURS, GOB HAD
DONE $45,000 IN DAMAGE.
- IN THERE, PLEASE.
- HEY, WHERE'S MY DESK?
- OH, I THINK
IT'S THE MASSAGE TABLE
IN THE BREAK ROOM NOW.
TAKE THE WINDOW.
- NO, HOLD IT.
GOB, MOM MAY THINK
THAT SHE'S GIVEN YOU MY JOB,
BUT THE BOARD STILL HAS TO
APPROVE THAT DECISION.
- ACTUALLY, THEY ALREADY HAVE.
- WHY SHOULD WE BELIEVE IN YOU?
- FOR THE SAME REASON
YOU SHOULD BELIEVE THAT
A HUNDRED-DOLLAR BILL...
IS NO MORE
THAN A HUNDRED PENNIES.
[gasping]
THEY APPROVED ME UNANIMOUSLY.
- WHY WOULDN'T THEY?
YOU'VE ONLY LOST THEM
$99 SO FAR.
- I'VE ALREADY BEEN
PRETTY SUCCESSFUL.
SHOWING THE MODEL HOUSE AGAIN.
SENT A REALTOR OVER THERE
YESTERDAY.
[narrator]
IT WAS THIS REALTOR
WHO'D RUN INTO LINDSAY,
THINKING SHE WAS
LOOKING FOR A HOME.
- I HAVE AN OPEN THING
GOIN' ON TOO.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE ADDRESS,
AND YOU CAN COME BY.
AND I THINK YOU'LL REALLY
LIKE THE NEIGHBORS.
- OKAY.
- SO WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE,
MICHAEL?
I HOPE IT'S NOT
FOR A HANDOUT.
I RUN A PRETTY TIGHT SHIP
AROUND HERE.
- WITH A POOL TABLE?
- IT'S A GAMING SHIP.
- I'M HERE BECAUSE
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT NEED ME.
- I NEED YOU?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- OH, BOY, THAT'S GOOD.
CAN'T WAIT TO CALL THE GUYS
IN TO HEAR THIS ONE.
LISTEN-- HOW DO YOU
INTERCOM ON THIS?
- STAR TWO.
- YEAH.
AT THE SAME TIME?
- YEAH, JUST--
NO, THE STAR IN THE CORNER.
THE STAR.
- SO IF I DO IT LIKE THAT--
- NO, TURN IT AROUND
THE OTHER WAY. STAR.
- OH, THAT STAR.
- LET'S JUST HANG IT UP.
THERE WE GO.
I-I THOUGHT THAT YOU MIGHT NEED
ME TO HELP YOU WITH THE BOOKS.
YOU KNOW,
THE CORPORATE CHECKBOOK.
WHERE IS IT?
- ACTUALLY, MOM'S GOT IT.
SHE WASN'T COMFORTABLE
WITH ME--
[narrator]
MICHAEL NOW HAD
THE DISTASTEFUL CHOICE...
OF EITHER ASKING HIS MOTHER
FOR MONEY OR GOING TO JAIL.
- MAYBE BUSTER
KILLED HER ALREADY.
[narrator]
TOBIAS WAS ALSO
HAVING A BAD DAY.
LINDSAY HAD MET SOMEONE,
AND HE HADN'T.
AND THAT'S WHEN HE FOUND WHAT
HE THOUGHT WAS A SUPPORT GROUP
FOR DEPRESSED MEN.
- WELL, IF IT ISN'T THE BOY
WHO CRIED "PHOENIX."
- OHH! NO, I WAS JUST, UH--
JUST WORRIED ABOUT BUSTER.
I THOUGHT MAYBE I SHOULD
GIVE HIM A LITTLE GUIDANCE.
WRITE HIM A CHECK.
BE A ROLE MODEL.
WHERE'S THE COMPANY CHECKBOOK?
- I ALREADY HAVE A NEW
ROLE MODEL, MICHAEL.
- HIS UNCLE OSCAR
IS LIVING HERE NOW.
- WOW.
YOU GUYS HAVE ACCOMPLISHED A LOT
IN THE LAST THREE HOURS.
WHERE IS HE?
- I SENT HIM OUT
FOR A NEW AIR HORN.
[bell dings]
[men grunting]
[ horn blasts ]
- YEAH!
- WE'VE GOT IT ALL
UNDER CONTROL.
- GREAT.
I'M JUST WORRIED
THAT IT'S ONLY GONNA BE
A MATTER OF TIME...
BEFORE THE MEDIA STARTS
PUTTING TOGETHER ALL THE PIECES
OF THIS IRAQ STORY.
[narrator]
MICHAEL HAD RECENTLY FOUND OUT
THAT THE MODEL HOME...
HE AND HIS SON
CURRENTLY LIVED IN...
WAS VERY SIMILAR TO SOME
HIS FATHER MAY HAVE ILLEGALLY
BEEN BUILDING IN IRAQ.
- THEY HAVEN'T YET.
AND FRANKLY, IT'S A VERY
DIFFICULT CHARGE TO PROVE.
- MAN, THAT JURY'S GONNA
FALL IN LOVE WITH YOU.
- WHAT DO YOU NEED,
MICHAEL?
- I DON'T NEED ANYTHING.
I'M GREAT, 'CAUSE
EVERYONE ELSE IS GREAT.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW NICE IT IS
TO NOT BE NEEDED ANYMORE.
- I WANT YOU.
- OKAY, THE JURY MIGHT
ACTUALLY LIKE THAT.
[narrator]
IT WAS AT THAT MOMENT
THAT GOB FOUND SOMETHING
THE JURY MIGHT NOT LIKE.
- HAMMER.
OOPS.
[narrator]
AND LINDSAY ARRIVED AT WHAT
SHE THOUGHT WAS A DATE.
- HEY!
YOU FOUND IT.
SO, SHALL WE START
IN THE KITCHEN?
- I THOUGHT THE BEDROOM.
- SURE.
I'LL MEET YOU UP THERE.
I GOTTA MAKE THIS PLACE
SMELL LIKE COOKIES.
AND YOU SHOULD KNOW,
I AM ANTICIPATING
MULTIPLES ON THIS.
- WELL, I WOULDN'T BE
DOING THIS IF I DIDN'T THINK
THAT WAS A POSSIBILITY.
[narrator]
LINDSAY WAS NERVOUS
AND TOOK A SHOWER TO RELAX.
- I CAN'T DO THIS.
I'M NOT READY FOR THIS.
[screams]
- COME ON, KIDS.
WE'LL GO DOWNSTAIRS
AND HAVE SOME COOKIES.
[narrator]
THE KIDS WERE IN
FOR SOME BAD NEWS TOO.
TOBIAS, MEANWHILE,
DISCOVERED THAT WHAT HE THOUGT
WAS A SUPPORT GROUP...
TURNED OUT TO BE A TEAM
OF BALD MEN PAINTED BLUE.
EVEN LUCILLE WAS ABOUT
TO FIND HERSELF IN TROUBLE.
- OH, YOU'VE DONE THIS
BEFORE.
- [chuckling]
- YOU KNOW, YOU SHOULD LET
YOUR HAIR GROW LONG.
- YEAH? I'VE THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
I GUESS I'D LOOK LIKE YOU.
[chuckling]
- MORE THAN YOU'LL EVER KNOW.
- ARE YOU LIVING IN ONE
OF SADDAM'S MANY PALACES?
THEY MAY HAVE BEEN BUILT
BY THE SAME DEVELOPER.
AND A SEAL ATTACK.
MEET ONE SURPRISED BATHER,
COMING UP.
- [giggling]
[narrator]
SEVEN MINUTES HAD PASSED SINCE
GOB HAD DISCOVERED THE DOCUMENT.
[intercom: woman]
GOB, YOUR MOTHER ON LINE ONE.
- I'M COMING OVER.
DON'T TALK TO ANYONE.
[narrator]
IT WAS AT THAT MOMENT
THAT LUCILLE WAS STOPPED
BY A DOCUMENTARY FILMMAKER.
- UH, YOUR COMPANY'S BEING
ACCUSED OF PROFITING OFF
THE BUILDING OF HOUSES IN IRAQ.
- THAT'S CRAZY.
WE'RE ALL LOYAL AMERICANS.
- OH, YEAH.
WOULD YOU ENLIST YOUR SON
OR DAUGHTER IN THE ARMY?
- YES.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS OUT OF OPTIONS...
AND, KNOWING THAT HIS FATHER
HAD A PENCHANT FOR HIDING
VALUABLE THINGS IN WALLS,
CONSIDERED ONE LAST
DESPERATE GAMBIT.
- THIS IS CRAZY.
WHAT AM I DOING?
USING A HAMMER TO TRY TO--
- [yells]
- [screams]
ARE YOU CRAZY?
- ARE YOU BLUE?
- ONLY IN COLOR, MICHAEL.
ONLY IN COLOR.
IT SEEMS I MIGHT
HAVE STUMBLED UPON
AN ACTING OPPORTUNITY.
- AS A MEMBER
OF THE BLUE MAN GROUP?
- OH, NO, YOU'RE THINKING
OF THE SUPPORT GROUP.
I MADE THAT
SAME MISTAKE MYSELF.
THEY'RE CALLED
THE BLUE MAN GROUP.
BUT IT'S FUNNY.
IF I HADN'T
SOUGHT OUT A SUPPORT GROUP,
I NEVER WOULD'VE GOTTEN
THIS GIG AS AN UNDERSTUDY
FOR A PERFORMANCE ART GROUP.
[clatter on floor]
YOU KNOW, THE UNIVERSE WORKS
IN MYSTERIOUS WAYS, MICHAEL.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHERE HELP
IS GOING TO COME FROM
UNTIL YOU LOOK FOR IT.
- WHY DOES EVERYBODY THINK
THAT I NEED HELP?
- [chuckles]
MICHAEL, LOOK AT YOU.
I MEAN, YOU'RE HOLDING
A SLEDGEHAMMER, YOUR SHIRT
IS COV-- OH, I DID THAT.
UM, HERE, LET ME, UH--
WELL--
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL REALIZED THAT
HE, TOO, HAD BEEN TOO PROUD.
- I NEED MONEY.
- I CAN'T HELP YOU.
- I KNOW.
IT DID BOTHER ME THAT THEY
DID SO WELL WITHOUT ME.
BUT I-I DO HAVE TO
ASK THEM FOR HELP.
- AND I HAVE TO ASK
FOR AN AUDITION.
- YOU HAVEN'T
AUDITIONED YET?
- OH, NO, NO.
I'M NOT IN THE GROUP YET.
NO, I'M AFRAID I
JUST "BLUE" MYSELF.
- THERE'S GOTTA BE
A BETTER WAY TO SAY THAT.
[narrator]
TOBIAS RUSHED TO THE THEATER,
HOPING TO BE SEEN.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT WAS DUSK,
AND HE COULDN'T BE SEEN.
[thumping]
- WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
[narrator]
SO, FOR THE SECOND
TIME IN TWO DAYS, THE FAMILY
GATHERED AT THE HOSPITAL.
- EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE OKAY.
I'M SURE HE'S GONNA BE FINE.
I'M SO SORRY THAT THIS HAPPENED.
I SPOKE TO HIM JUST BEFORE
HE LEFT THE HOUSE.
- OH, REALLY?
WHAT WAS
THE LAST THING HE SAID?
- I JUST "BLUE" MYSELF.
- HE SAID SOME
WONDERFUL THINGS,
INCLUDING THE FACT
THAT SOMETIMES PEOPLE...
ARE TOO PROUD TO ASK FOR HELP
WHEN THEY NEED IT.
- OH, GOD! FINE. I NEED YOU!
- I NEED YOU, OKAY, MICHAEL?
- NO, I-I DIDN'T MEAN FOR--
- HE WAS A REALTOR, MICHAEL.
NOW MY HUSBAND'S
IN THE HOSPITAL.
- MOM VOLUNTEERED ME
FOR THE ARMY JUST BECAUSE
THE FAT MAN DARED HER TO.
- WE CAN'T LET THEM TAKE BUSTER.
- I LOST MY WIG,
MY UNCLE SAM WIG.
- MICHAEL, I AM SITTING ON SOME
VERY HOT INFORMATION HERE.
I KNOW TOO MUCH.
I'VE GOT THE THINGY.
HALF IN ENGLISH,
HALF IN SCRIBBLY.
- MICHAEL, PLEASE,
WE NEED YOU!
- WELL, I HATE TO CANCEL MY
MEDICAL FOLLOW-UP IN PHOENIX,
BUT YOU GIVE ME
THE CORPORATE CHECKBOOK,
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
- EXCUSE ME.
MRS. FUNKE
- OH, THIS GUY AGAIN.
- HOW IS HE, DOCTOR?
- IT, UH, LOOKS LIKE HE'S DEAD.
- OH, MY GOD!
- OH, LITTLE GUY!
THE TEARS AREN'T COMING!
THE TEARS JUST AREN'T COMING!
- OKAY, OKAY.
- UH, JUST TO BE CLEAR--
LOOKS LIKE HE'S DEAD,
OR HE IS DEAD?
- IT JUST LOOKS
LIKE HE'S DEAD.
HE'S GOT, LIKE,
BLUE PAINT ON HIM OR SOMETHING,
BUT HE'S GOING TO BE FINE.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
- WHAT A--
[bleep] DOCTOR!
- I'LL LET YOU
CELEBRATE PRIVATELY.
- HEY, WE WANT THIS COMPED!
- WELL, I'M GONNA--
I'M JUST GONNA HEAD OUT.
YOU DON'T NEED SOME, UH,
PIECE OF-- [bleep]
UNCLE HANGING AROUND.
- HEY, HEY! THAT'S NOT MY DAD.
THAT'S NOT THE GUY YOU WANT.
IF YOU WANT ANYBODY, IT'S ME.
- WHAT?
- MICHAEL?
- YEAH.
I GOTTA TURN MYSELF IN
OR MAKE BAIL,
UH, MAYBE BY, LIKE, 8:00.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
WHOA, HEY.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO
HAVE THAT LOOKED AT.
- THANKS, MIKEY.
[kisses]
- THEY THINK I'M INVOLVED
IN THIS IRAQ THING,
AND I CAN'T PROVE THAT I'M NOT
WITH DAD NOT AROUND,
SO I NEED YOUR HELP
OR I'M GONNA GO TO JAIL.
- WE'VE GOT THE PROOF, MICHAEL.
DAD'S SIGNED CONTRACT
WITH SADDAM.
- [whispers]
HUSSEIN.
- USE IT.
IF IT MAKES YOUR FATHER
LOOK BAD, THEN SO BE IT.
HE'S LONG GONE NOW.
- HEY, UH,
WHERE'S THE BRIEFCASE?
- OSCAR HAS IT.
- HEY, I'M AWFULLY SORRY
I'M LATE.
I GOT HERE AS FAST AS I--
OH, HOW IS HE?
- DID YOU JUST
CHANGE YOUR CLOTHES?
- HEY, LOOK WHAT I FOUND
ON WINDOWSILL.
JUST HAT.
SOMEONE TAKE WIG.
[narrator]
IN FACT, IT WAS GEORGE SR.
WHO TOOK WIG...
- HIT IT!
AND WAS FLEEING THE COUNTRY
WITH THE EVIDENCE...
MICHAEL SO BADLY NEEDED.
- YOU MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
LINDSAY ALMOST STUMBLES
UPON A DATING OPPORTUNITY.
- YOU LOOK REALLY HOT.
[narrator]
BUT INSTEAD,
IS ADMITTED TO THE HOSPITAL
WITH A FEVER OF 104.
MICHAEL FINALLY GETS
THE CORPORATE CHECKBOOK,
ONLY TO FIND THAT THE FAMILY
HAS GOTTEN TO IT FIRST.
AND BARRY LANDS IN JAIL.
- YOU'RE GLAD TOBIAS
IS PRESSING CHARGES?
- I AM HAVING
THE TIME OF MY LIFE.
- HEY.
- HEY, DR. HATE.
- [guard]
NO TOUCHING!
- [exhales]