male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING,
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
narrator:
MICHAEL BLUTH WAS AT HOME
WORKING ON A PLAN
TO SAVE THE COMPANY.
- HOW'S THIS
FOR A BUSINESS MODEL?
WE MAKE THE COMPANY
LOOK LIKE IT'S IN THE BLACK
BY STARTING CONSTRUCTION
ON THE PHASE TWO DEVELOPMENT.
NOW, I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING.
WE'RE NOT IN THE BLACK.
HOW'RE WE GONNA BUILD 30 HOUSES
WITHOUT ANY MONEY?
WE DON'T--WE BUILD ONE,
THEN WE HAVE A HUGE
RIBBON-CUTTING CEREMONY
WHILE WE'RE THE RAISING FUNDS
FOR THE OTHERS.
narrator:
MICHAEL'S FATHER ALWAYS UNVEILED
HIS CONSTRUCTION PROJECTS
WITH A HIGHLY PUBLICIZED
RIBBON-CUTTING CEREMONY.
HE EVEN DID SO
FOR THE PRISON HE BUILT,
AND, SOMEWHAT IRONICALLY,
WOULD LATER OCCUPY.
- THE ONLY DIFFERENCE IS THIS
TIME I GET TO CUT THE RIBBON.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- THERE'S A CREAM
WITH REAL DIAMONDS IN IT.
I CAN ACTUALLY SMEAR DIAMONDS
ON MY FACE,
AND IT'S ONLY $400 A TUB.
THAT'S LIKE, WHAT, LIKE,
A MILLION DIAMONDS FOR $400?
- MM.
- A MILLION
[bleep] DIAMONDS.
- OKAY.
- IS SHE ON YOU
ABOUT THAT DIAMOND CREAM?
- MY HUSBAND'S JEALOUS BECAUSE
SINCE WE DECIDED TO HAVE
AN OPEN MARRIAGE,
I'VE BEEN DOING
A LITTLE BETTER THAN HE HAS.
- IT IS NOT A COMPETITION,
LINDSAY.
WE ARE DOING THIS
TO SAVE OUR MARRIAGE.
BUT I SHOULD BE TELLING YOU
THAT I HAVE BEEN MEETING
MY FAIR SHARE OF GROUPIES.
OR SHOULD I SAY "BLUEPIES"?
narrator: TOBIAS HAD RECENTLY
AUDITIONED AS AN UNDERSTUDY
FOR THE SILENT PERFORMANCE
ART TRIO, THE BLUE MAN GROUP.
- AND THIS IS "KIDS"
FROM "BYE, BYE, BIRDIE."
narrator: HE HAD YET TO HEAR
BACK FROM THEM.
- DO YOU GUYS REALLY THINK
YOU HAVE THE GUTS
TO GO THROUGH WITH THIS
"SEEING OTHER PEOPLE" THING?
narrator: IN FACT, NEITHER
LINDSAY NOR TOBIAS
DID HAVE THE GUTS TO GO
THROUGH WITH IT.
- I ALREADY HAVE.
- I HAVE TOO.
CAN I BUY YOU A DRINK?
- NO.
narrator: LINDSAY, BECAUSE
SHE'D LOST HER SELF-CONFIDENCE.
- I'D LIKE TO BUY YOU A DRINK.
WHERE'S SHE GOING?
narrator: AND TOBIAS,
BECAUSE HE WAS BUSY
KEEPING AN EYE ON LINDSAY.
- WHO ARE YOU GONNA BRING
TO THIS RIBBON-CUTTING DANCE?
- IT'S NOT A DANCE,
AND YOU DON'T NEED A DATE.
ALTHOUGH, GEORGE MICHAEL,
I'D LOVE FOR YOU TO COME WITH ME
WHEN I CUT THE RIBBON
AT THE NEW HOUSE.
- OH, WOW.
HEY, CAN I BRING ANN?
- WHO?
- ANN.
YOU KNOW, SHE'S--SHE'S THE GIRL
I'M KINDA HANGING OUT WITH.
- I HAVEN'T MET ANN.
- YES, YOU HAVE.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD MET ANN.
- YOU LET HER IN.
SEE, THAT'S HER
RIGHT OVER THERE.
- OH, ANN.
YES, YES, YES, YES.
YEAH. I KNOW ANN.
HEY, YOU!
SHE'S GOT A LITTLE
HARD-BOILED EGG GOING THERE.
- OH, IT'S SO CUTE.
SHE SOMETIMES TAKES
A LITTLE PACK OF MAYONNAISE,
AND SHE'LL SQUIRT IT
IN HER MOUTH,
AND THEN SHE'LL TAKE AN EGG
AND KIND OF--MMM.
SHE CALLS IT A MAYONN-EGG.
ARE YOU OKAY?
- I DON'T FEEL SO GOOD.
- YOU KNOW, I KIND OF WANT
TO BUY HER A DIAMOND.
- HER?
- ANN.
I MEAN,
I KNOW I CAN'T AFFORD IT,
BUT AUNT LINDSAY WAS TELLING ME
ABOUT THIS DIAMOND CREAM.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, I'M SURE
THAT EGG IS A VERY NICE PERSON.
I JUST DON'T WANT YOU SPENDING--
- IT'S ANN. HER NA--
- ALL YOUR MONEY GETTING HER
ALL GLITTERED UP FOR EASTER,
YOU KNOW?
MORE IMPORTANTLY,
I WANT US TO DO THIS TOGETHER.
KINDA LIKE A FATHER-SON
SORT OF THING, YOU KNOW?
AND SINCE POP-POP IS NO LONGER
PRESIDENT, WE GET TO DO IT.
- BUT I THOUGHT GOB
WAS PRESIDENT NOW.
- YEAH, AND I DON'T HAVE
ANY PROBLEM WITH THAT.
narrator:
IN FACT,
SINCE MICHAEL'S FATHER ESCAPED
FROM PRISON,
HIS BROTHER GOB HAD BEEN MADE
PRESIDENT, ALBEIT IN NAME ONLY.
WHICH IS WHY MICHAEL
WAS SURPRISED
WHEN HE GOT TO WORK
THE NEXT DAY.
- YOU'RE STILL IN MY OFFICE.
- GOSH, MICHAEL,
I AM KIND OF THE PRESIDENT.
- AND I HAVE NO PROBLEM
WITH THAT.
BUT IT IS
JUST A TITLE, REMEMBER?
YOU KNOW, JUST DOING THIS
TO APPEASE THE STOCKHOLDERS
WHILE THEY SCRUTINIZE ME
FOR DAD'S CRIMES.
- HEY, LOOK, DAD MAY HAVE
ILLEGALLY BUILT
SOME HOMES IN IRAQ,
WHICH IS KINDA NOT COOL.
- I KNOW, BUT THAT'S WHY
I'VE GOT A BUSINESS MODEL
THAT I THINK IS GOING TO RESTORE
THE IMAGE OF OUR COMPANY.
WE'RE GOING TO BUILD
A SECOND MODEL HOME.
- THAT'S GREAT.
CAN I ANNOUNCE IT TO THE BOARD?
- GEE, IT IS MY BUSINESS MODEL.
IF YOU HAD A BUSINESS MODEL,
THEN BY ALL MEANS,
GO IN THERE
AND DO YOUR LITTLE DANCE.
- TELL YOU WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO.
ROCK, PAPER, SCISSORS FOR IT.
- NO, NO, I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN DOING--
- ONE, TWO, THREE.
PAPER COVERS ROCK.
- IT IS A ROCK, THOUGH.
IT SHOULD BEAT EVERYTHING.
- THERE'S NOT A LOT OF LOGIC
TO IT.
IT'S LIKE ON A BOAT
WITH "WOMEN AND CHILDREN FIRST."
WHY SHOULD THEY--
WHICH, BEFORE I FORGET,
I'M BUYING A COMPANY BOAT.
- SORRY?
narrator: THAT MORNING,
GOB HAD GONE TO A BOAT SHOW,
WHERE HE SAW SOMETHING
HE WANTED.
- HELLO.
- HI.
- WHAT A BEAUTY.
- THANK YOU.
- I MEANT YOU.
- WELL.
narrator: GOB FLIRTED
WITH HER FOR A WHILE
AND FINALLY ASKED
FOR HER NUMBER.
- LET'S GET SOME DIGITS.
- I'M SORRY, I DON'T GIVE IT OUT
WITHOUT A FIRM OFFER.
- OH, I'LL MAKE YOU
A FIRM OFFER.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
SHE WASN'T FLIRTING.
- AND HERE AGAIN, PLEASE.
- THE SEAWARD.
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING A BOAT.
- ONE, TWO, THREE.
- NOPE, NOT GONNA DO IT.
- PAPER COVERS ROCK.
- FINE. BUT ROCK SINKS BOAT.
- MICHAEL?
- MOM, I'M RIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE OF SOMETHING.
GET RID OF THE SEAWARD.
- I'LL LEAVE WHEN
I'M GOOD AND READY.
IT'S ABOUT YOUR UNCLE OSCAR.
I WANT HIM TO MOVE IN WITH YOU.
- YOU'RE NOT KICKING HIM OUT
ALREADY, ARE YOU?
narrator: MICHAEL'S UNCLE
HAD RECENTLY MOVED
INTO LUCILLE'S APARTMENT,
WHERE THEY QUICKLY REKINDLED
A LONG-DORMANT ROMANCE.
IT WAS A SECRET
SHE HOPED TO KEEP--
- OSCAR, WE'LL BE HEARD.
narrator: AND HE DIDN'T.
- THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT SO HOT.
- MOTHER?
MOTHER!
I HEARD ZOO NOISES.
- IT'S NOTHING. GO BACK TO BED.
- SO EVERYBODY'S STILL UP, HUH?
- [whimpering]
- IT'S NOT FAIR TO BUSTER.
HE'S A NERVOUS WRECK RIGHT NOW.
HE'S GOING INTO THE ARMY,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
- YOU VOLUNTEERED HIM.
- I KNEW YOU WERE GOING TO
THROW THAT IN MY FACE.
- WELL, DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT,
OKAY?
THEY'RE NEVER GONNA
TAKE HIM ANYWAY.
narrator:
AT THAT MOMENT,
BUSTER WAS TAKING HIS PHYSICAL
AT THE RECRUITMENT CENTER.
- I HAVE A HOLE
IN MY HEART.
I'VE NEVER OPENED MY EYES
UNDERWATER.
MY [whispers]
REPRODUCTIVE ORGAN
IS SHAPED LIKE [whispers]
A LOBSTER TAIL,
BUT WITHOUT ITS SHELL,
HMM?
OH, I GUESS I HAVE THE PANIC
ATTACKS UNDER CONTROL.
OH, AND I'M LEGALLY BLIND
AT NIGHT.
narrator: BUT BUSTER
HAD MISCALCULATED
THE ARMY'S CURRENT NEED
FOR PERSONNEL.
- OKAY, THEN, LET'S GET
YOU FITTED FOR A UNIFORM.
- WHAT? WHAT?
- HEY, WHY DON'T YOU
VOLUNTEER OSCAR?
THAT WOULD SOLVE
BOTH OF YOUR PROBLEMS.
- HE'D NEVER CUT HIS HAIR.
[inhales]
THAT HAIR.
- LISTEN, OSCAR'S YOUR PROBLEM.
I'M TAKING CARE OF EVERYTHING
ELSE IN THIS FAMILY,
INCLUDING STARTING CONSTRUCTION
ON A SECOND MODEL HOME.
WE'RE HAVING
A RIBBON-CUTTING CEREMONY.
- MICHAEL, WE CAN'T HAVE
A RIBBON-CUTTING
WITHOUT YOUR FATHER,
AND HE'S GOD KNOWS WHERE.
narrator:
GEORGE SR. WAS IN MEXICO
WITH HIS ESCAPE ACCOMPLICE
AND EX-SECRETARY, KITTY.
- I KEEP EATING SO MANY EGGS.
IT MUST BE MY UNCONSCIOUS DESIRE
TO HAVE A BABY.
OH, MY GOD.
CAN YOU EVEN IMAGINE
HOW CUTE
THE COMBINATION
OF THE TWO OF US WOULD BE?
I MEAN, WE'RE ALL OUT OF
"PROPHYLACTICOS" ANYWAY.
SOMEBODY USED THE LAST TWO
ON HIS FEET
TO WALK ACROSS
THE BATHROOM FLOOR.
narrator:
BUT HE WAS GROWING TIRED
OF THEIR CONFINED INTIMACY.
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
HEY, IT'S ME.
- DAD?
- YEAH. LISTEN, I GOTTA
MAKE THIS QUICK.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN SAVE
THE FAMILY,
BUT YOU GOTTA KEEP
THE COMPANY STRONG,
BECAUSE I'M GONNA NEED
SOME OF THAT MONEY LATER.
- I WILL, DAD.
IT'S FUNNY,
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS OF
YOU MAKING FUN OF ME
FOR THE MAGIC SHOWS AND--
- GOB!
OH, FOR GOD'S--I CALLED TO TALK
TO MICHAEL, YOU HORSE'S--
[female operator speaking
in Spanish]
narrator:
GOB WAS HURT.
- BYE, POP.
- HEY, WHOA, WHOA,
WAS THAT DAD?
- YEAH, I HAD TO, UH,
JUMP OFF.
- YOU JUST HAD DAD ON THE PHONE?
WHERE WAS HE?
- NO WAY TO TELL, REALLY.
PORTUGAL.
DOWN SOUTH AMERICA WAY.
- WELL, DID HE WANNA
TALK TO ME?
- NO, HE WANTED TO TALK
TO THE PRESIDENT.
- I HAVE NO PROBLEM WITH THAT.
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS ALSO HURT.
AND GEORGE SR.
WAS BRUTALLY HURT
WHEN HE WAS MISTAKEN
FOR HIS TWIN BROTHER OSCAR.
- [speaking in Spanish]
- MARIJUANA? NO, NO.
THAT'S MY BROTHER.
BROTHERO. BROTHERO.
narrator: THAT NIGHT,
LINDSAY HEADED TO THE CLUB
TO TRY AGAIN TO MEET SOMEONE.
SOON, HAVING STRUCK OUT AGAIN,
SHE SPOTTED A MAN
WHO LOOKED INTERESTING.
HE HAD THE LEAN LOOK,
EFFORTLESS HAIR,
AND DRESSED-DOWN MANNER
OF A MOVIE STAR.
- BUY ME A DRINK?
- I THINK THE BARS ARE CLOSING.
- I KNOW A PLACE.
narrator:
IT WAS AT THAT POINT
THAT LINDSAY HAD
A STARTLING REVELATION.
- UH-UH-UH, YOU GET OUT.
GET OUT. GET OUT. OUT, OUT, OUT!
NO HOMELESS IN HERE!
- HOMELESS?
YOU'RE HOMELESS?
YOU'RE GROSS.
OH, GOD.
[slow jazz music]
- THEY'RE TAKING ME IN THE ARMY.
THEY DIDN'T THINK THERE WAS
ENOUGH WRONG WITH ME.
- WELL, DID THEY
CHECK EVERYTHING?
- YES. THEY EVEN TOUCHED
MY CHARLIE BROWNS.
YOU LIED TO ME.
YOU SAID I WASN'T FIT TO SERVE.
- OKAY, HOLD ON.
LET'S CALM DOWN, PEOPLE.
UM, I THINK I KNOW A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT AVOIDING COMBAT DUTY.
NOW, WHICH PINKIE
DO YOU USE LESS?
- ARE YOU NUTS?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT I WENT THROUGH
TO HAVE THIS BOY?
- OH, I KNOW WHERE THE BOY
CAME FROM.
- WAIT.
WHY WERE YOU IN THE PANTRY?
narrator: AND LUCILLE REALIZED
IT WAS TIME TO END
WHATEVER IT WAS
SHE HAD WITH OSCAR.
- SO I BELIEVE
IT'S A GOOD PLAN.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY, MICHAEL
WAS READY TO WOW THE BOARD
WITH HIS NEW BUSINESS MODEL.
- AS I TOLD MY BROTHER,
THE PRESIDENT,
IF WE START CONSTRUCTION
ON A SECOND MODEL HOME,
WE CAN BE CUTTING THIS RIBBON
WITHIN TWO MONTHS.
- I SAID, "THAT'S WHY
YOU'RE NO LONGER PRESIDENT."
TWO WEEKS.
LET'S DO IT IN TWO WEEKS.
HEY!
[upbeat synth music playing]
- I'M SORRY. I'M SORRY.
CAN WE STOP THE MUSIC?
I'M NOT AS OPTIMISTIC
THAT WE CAN GET THAT DONE.
GOB, I THINK WE BOTH AGREE THAT
WE WOULD DO THINGS YOUR WAY
IF YOU HAD
A BUSINESS MODEL.
DO YOU HAVE
A BUSINESS MODEL, GOB?
- I AM SO HAPPY
THAT YOU ASKED ME THAT, MICHAEL,
BECAUSE I JUST HAPPEN TO HAVE
A BUSINESS MODEL RIGHT HERE.
[music resumes]
- [singing]
SOLID AS A ROCK
- MEET STARLA, THE NEW BLUTH
COMPANY BUSINESS MODEL
FOR OUR PHASE TWO CAMPAIGN.
- BLUTH HOMES:
SOLID AS A ROCK.
- WE'LL SEE YOU AT
THE RIBBON-CUTTING IN TWO WEEKS
IF MY BROTHER DOESN'T
SCREW IT UP FIRST.
HEY!
- [singing] SOLID AS A ROCK
narrator:
GOB HAD JUST COMMITTED MICHAEL
TO BUILDING A MODEL HOME
IN TWO WEEKS.
- WE CAN'T BUILD A HOUSE
ALSO, I'M NOT SO SURE
HOW "SOLID AS A ROCK"
HELPS PEOPLE FORGET THE FACT
THAT WE BUILT HOUSES IN IRAQ.
- I LOVE THAT.
- BUT YOU PROBABLY KNOW BEST
BECAUSE YOU'RE PRESIDENT.
- WE DON'T HAVE TO BUILD
A REAL HOUSE, MICHAEL.
LIKE YOU SAID,
IT'S ALL FOR APPEARANCES ANYWAY.
WE THROW UP A COUPLE OF WALLS.
WE BUILD A FAKE ONE.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- NOTHING ON THE INSIDE.
- I'LL NEVER GET
A CREW TO BUILD IT.
THEY'D LOSE THEIR LICENSES.
- THEN YOU BUILD IT
YOURSELF, DAMN IT!
HEY, THERE SHE IS,
MY LITTLE BUSINESS MODEL.
SORRY ABOUT THAT
"BUILD IT YOURSELF" CRAP.
I'M THINKING I MIGHT TAKE HER
TO THE RIBBON-CUTTING.
YOU END UP FINDING
A DATE YET?
- NO.
narrator:
AS MICHAEL GREW FRUSTRATED
BY HIS RELATIONSHIP WITH GOB,
LUCILLE TRIED TO END HERS
WITH OSCAR.
- I WANT YOU
OUT OF THE HOUSE.
- OH, I WANT YOU EVERYWHERE.
- OSCAR, NO.
I CAN'T HAVE
THIS IN MY LIFE ANYMORE.
I'M A MARRIED WOMAN.
- LUCILLE, YOU WANNA LEAVE?
I WON'T CHASE AFTER YOU.
BUT BEFORE YOU DO, ASK YOURSELF,
"WHERE'S YOUR HUSBAND?"
BECAUSE I AM HERE.
I AM REAL.
I AM FLESH AND BLOOD.
AND HAIR.
- OH, GOD, THAT HAIR.
[sighs]
WHAT WILL PEOPLE SAY?
- THEY'LL SAY,
"THOSE PEOPLE ARE IN LOVE."
narrator: THAT NIGHT,
THE EVENING NEWS REPORT
SAID SOMETHING VERY DIFFERENT.
- LUCILLE BLUTH
CAUGHT ON TAPE
BREATHING LIFE
INTO A HOMELESS MAN.
THE SURPRISING HOME VIDEO
AT 10:00.
narrator: AND MICHAEL PREPARED
TO BUILD A HOUSE.
- TWO WEEKS?
BUT WHAT IF MY DATE'S
NOT AVAILABLE?
- I'M TRYING TO GET
A LAST-MINUTE CREW TOGETHER.
LINDSAY, YOUR INABILITY
TO GET A MAN INTERESTED
IS NOT AT THE TOP OF MY LIST.
- OH, I'VE GOT A MAN
INTERESTED, MICHAEL.
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH HIM?
- THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH HIM.
HE IS HOMELESS.
WELL, I DIDN'T KNOW
HE WAS HOMELESS AT THE TIME.
IT WAS HUMILIATING.
- IS THIS ABOUT
GANGY'S HOMELESS GUY?
- GANGY'S HOMELESS GUY?
- YEAH, IT'S ALL OVER THE NEWS.
GANGY GAVE C.P.R. TO
A HOMELESS GUY ON THE BEACH.
narrator: LINDSAY FELT RESPECT
FOR HER MOTHER
AND DECIDED THAT PERHAPS
SHE COULD OVERCOME HER PRIDE
AND HELP SOMEONE TOO.
- I'VE GOT SOMEONE
FOR YOUR CREW, MICHAEL.
MY BOYFRIEND, THE HOMELESS GUY.
I WONDER IF HE EVEN
HAS AN APARTMENT OR--
[phone ringing]
- HELLO?
- DID YOU SEE THE NEWS?
YOUR UNCLE OSCAR FORCED HIMSELF
ON ME AT THE BEACH TODAY,
AND I DIDN'T HAVE MY HORN.
- OF COURSE.
IT WAS UNCLE OSCAR.
MOM, YOU'RE NOT HAVING
AN AFFAIR WITH HIM, ARE YOU?
- YOU'RE BUILDING A HOUSE.
I WANT YOU TO GIVE IT TO HIM.
- IT'S NOT A REAL HOUSE.
- PERFECT. HE'S NOT A REAL MAN.
narrator: AND GEORGE SR. MADE
HIS CASE TO THE MEXICAN POLICE.
- MY GOD, I WAS BEATEN UP HERE.
I'M TELLING YOU.
I'M GEORGE.
I'M NOT OSCAR. I'M GEORGE.
- THE CORNBALLER.
- SI, THE CORNBALLER.
narrator: GEORGE SR.
HAD MARKETED A DEVICE
CALLED THE CORNBALLER IN MEXICO
AFTER THE SEVERE BURNS IT CAUSED
LED TO IT BEING BANNED
IN THE U.S.
- WHY, DID YOU HAVE ONE?
- SI.
narrator: LINDSAY, MEANWHILE,
WAS HAVING TROUBLE
FINDING HER HOMELESS MAN.
- HE LOOKED LIKE A MOVIE STAR.
narrator: IN FACT,
THE MAN LOOKED LIKE A MOVIE STAR
BECAUSE HE WAS A MOVIE STAR.
HIS NAME WAS TOM JANE,
AND HE WAS MAKING TWO MOVIES
FOR A MAJOR STUDIO.
ONE WAS A GRITTY PERSONAL
PROJECT ABOUT A JUNKIE'S LIFE,
WHICH HE ONLY GOT TO DO
IN EXCHANGE FOR MAKING
A RIGIDLY
FORMULAIC POPCORN MOVIE.
HE WAS LIVING ON THE STREETS,
RESEARCHING HIS ROLE.
- HEY, HOMELESS GUY.
- HEY.
- I'M NOT PROUD OF THE WAY
I WAS SO GROSSED OUT
WHEN I FOUND OUT
YOU WERE GROSS BEFORE.
- YOU REALLY THOUGHT
I WAS GROSS, HUH?
- WELL, AT FIRST, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE KIND OF HOT,
BUT I HADN'T LOOKED
CLOSELY ENOUGH.
LISTEN, I HAVE
A CONSTRUCTION JOB FOR YOU.
AND IF YOU CLEAN YOURSELF UP,
WHO KNOWS?
YOU MIGHT ACTUALLY
GET A DATE OUT OF THIS.
OKAY.
- SEE YA.
- OKAY, WE'VE ALL MADE
SOME SACRIFICES TO BE HERE,
BUT WE ALL WANT THE SAME THING.
- I WANNA LIVE HERE.
- I WANNA BUY ANN
SOME DIAMOND DUST.
- I'M JUST HOPING
TO GET MILDLY INJURED,
SO I CAN GET OUT OF THE ARMY.
- BOTTOM LINE IS WE'VE GOT
TWO WEEKS TO BUILD A HOUSE.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE GOOD.
IT JUST HAS TO LOOK GOOD.
- I JUST WANT MY KIDS BACK.
narrator: AND SO
THE GUYS WENT TO WORK.
- [grunting]
[chattering]
narrator: THINGS DIDN'T GO
SMOOTHLY AT FIRST.
BUSTER LOOKED FOR WAYS
TO HURT HIMSELF.
BUT SOON THE PROJECT
CAME TOGETHER
WHEN GOB STOPPED BY.
- NOW WE'RE BUILDING A HOUSE.
- YEAH, I'M PRETTY PROUD--
- SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DID I DO THIS OR WHAT?
- SEEMS LIKE
YOUR BROTHER DID IT.
- MY BROTHER DOES
WHAT I TELL HIM TO DO.
I'M THE PRESIDENT.
- WHERE'S YOUR "P"?
- WHAT?
OH, NO, NOT AGAIN.
- I GOT IT.
- [groans]
HEY, SORRY FOR THE
"MY BROTHER DOES WHAT I TELL HIM
TO DO" CRAP,
BUT I WANT THIS TO BE PERFECT
FOR WHEN I CUT
THE RIBBON TOMORROW.
- YOU'RE CUTTING THE RIBBON?
I KINDA THOUGHT
THAT SINCE I BUILT IT,
I MIGHT GO AHEAD
AND GIVE IT A--
- YEAH, OKAY.
CAN YOU IMAGINE HOW THAT WOULD
LOOK TO THE BOARD?
THE CONSTRUCTION WORKER
CUTTING THE RIBBON.
NO, NO, THAT'S A JOB
FOR THE PRESIDENT.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD A PROBLEM WITH THAT.
GOB HAD TAKEN AWAY SOMETHING
MICHAEL ALWAYS WANTED.
- YOU GOT THE "P."
narrator:
NOW IT WAS MICHAEL'S TURN
TO TAKE SOMETHING FROM GOB--
STARLA.
AND LATER, MICHAEL
SET ABOUT HIS PLAN.
- GOB, DO YOU HAVE
STARLA'S PHONE NUMBER?
I GOT A FEW BUSINESS THINGS
I'D LIKE TO GO OVER
WITH THE BUSINESS MODEL.
- GUESS WHO WAS JUST OVER HER?
DON'T, I'LL TELL YOU--ME.
- HMM?
- I [bleep] THE BUSINESS MODEL.
narrator:
ACTUALLY, THEY JUST MADE OUT.
- YEAH, SHE HAD
ALL KINDS OF ORGASMS.
IMAGINE THAT.
I FINALLY NAILED SOMEBODY
THAT YOU WEREN'T AFTER.
- ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT.
I'VE WORKED TOO HARD
AND TOO LONG
FOR YOU TO KEEP GETTING
ALL THE CREDIT.
I BUILT THAT COMPANY.
I BUILT THAT HOUSE.
AND I'M GONNA
BE CUTTING THE RIBBON,
WHETHER WE'RE ALL PRETENDING
THAT YOU'RE PRESIDENT OR NOT.
- YEAH, SURE.
I JUST WANTED--
- YOU JUST WANTED WHAT?
- I JUST WANTED YOU
TO BE IMPRESSED WITH ME.
DAD NEVER WAS.
NEVER SAID A NICE THING
ABOUT ME.
- HE CALLED YOU THE OTHER DAY.
HE DIDN'T EVEN WANNA TALK TO ME.
- OF COURSE HE DID!
HE NEVER WANTS TO TALK TO ME.
HE NEVER HAS.
- CUT THE RIBBON.
- REALLY?
- YEAH. HOW ABOUT THAT?
- MICHAEL.
- I HAVE NO PROBLEM WITH IT.
ALL RIGHT?
TAKE IT EASY.
- THANK YOU.
- COME ON.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY,
THE BLUTH FAMILY PREPARED
TO UNVEIL PHASE TWO.
- HAVE YOU SEEN
YOUR UNCLE GOB AROUND?
- NO, AND I CAN'T FIND
THAT DIAMOND DUST
THAT AUNT LINDSAY BOUGHT FOR ME.
- OH, WELL, YOUR AUNT LINDSAY
HAS PROBABLY TAKEN IT.
SHE'S JUST A TAKER.
- THIS IS YOUR CHANCE, HUH?
WITH THE BIG RIBBON-CUTTERS
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS?
- WELL, ACTUALLY, I FIGURED,
GIVE GOB A CHANCE, YOU KNOW?
THE GUY DOESN'T GET A WHOLE LOT
OF ATTENTION IN THIS FAMILY.
- LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE PRESIDENT OF
THE BLUTH COMPANY, GOB BLUTH.
- MY BROTHER WASN'T OPTIMISTIC
IT COULD BE DONE.
BUT I DIDN'T TAKE "WASN'T
OPTIMISTIC IT COULD BE DONE"
FOR AN ANSWER.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I PRESENT TO YOU
PHASE TWO
OF THE BLUTH COMPANY.
A HOUSE TRULY
SOLID AS A ROCK.
[applause]
- [singing]
SOLID AS A ROCK
[wood creaking]
narrator:
BUT AS IT TURNS OUT,
MICHAEL WAS RIGHT TO NOT BE
OPTIMISTIC IT COULD BE DONE.
[people screaming]
narrator: AND BUSTER SAW
THE CHANCE TO GET INJURED ENOUGH
TO KEEP HIM OUT OF THE ARMY.
- [whimpering]
narrator: BUT INSTEAD,
GOT A GLIMPSE INSIDE.
- I CAN'T LOOK AT THAT.
narrator:
UNFORTUNATELY, TOBIAS HAD TO.
- I GOT THE WRONG HOMELESS MAN.
I AM SORRY.
I WAS LOOKING FOR LINDSAY.
- YOU LIED TO ME.
YOU BOTH LIED TO ME.
I'M GOING TO WAR.
- BUSTER, YOU CAN'T!
- YES, I CAN.
I DON'T AGREE
WITH YOUR DIRTY DOINGS HERE,
BUT I WILL DEFEND WITH MY LIFE
YOUR RIGHT TO DO IT.
- YOU PLANNED THIS ALL ALONG,
DIDN'T YOU, MICHAEL?
- NO, I DIDN'T.
I HAD NO CREW. I HAD NO TIME.
- YOU SET ME UP.
narrator: GOB CHARGED AT MICHAEL
WITH THE SCISSORS,
BUT MICHAEL, AS HE ALWAYS DID,
PICKED ROCK.
- YOU WANTED TO MAKE ME
LOOK FOOLISH!
- PUT DOWN THE SCISSORS.
- PUT 'EM DOWN.
- FOOLISH WITH SCISSORS!
narrator:
WHICH BEAT SCISSORS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE WHOLE INCIDENT
WAS COVERED BY THE PAPER.
- NOBODY LOOKS GOOD IN THIS.
- ESPECIALLY THAT LITTLE DUDE.
- THAT'S ANN.
- WHO'S--
- IT DOESN'T MATTER. LISTEN.
YOU KNOW I DIDN'T SET YOU UP,
OKAY?
AND I REALLY THINK THE ONLY
REASON YOU AND I ALWAYS FIGHT
IS THAT SINCE WE WERE
LITTLE KIDS,
DAD'S ALWAYS PLAYED US
OFF EACH OTHER.
- DAD ALWAYS SAID
THAT WAS YOUR FAULT.
- ANYWAY, WHAT WE OUGHT TO DO
IS MAKE A DECISION RIGHT NOW
NOT TO LET DAD GET IN THE MIDDLE
OF OUR RELATIONSHIP ANYMORE.
I MEAN, HE'S NOT EVEN IN TOWN,
AND WE'RE FIGHTING.
- WE'RE GROWN MEN.
- YEAH, LET'S JUST MOVE ON.
- LOOK AT ME.
I'M THE PRESIDENT
OF A COMPANY NOW.
[phone ringing]
- OH, THAT'S DAD'S LINE.
I BET HE SAW THE PAPER.
- LISTEN, IF YOU WANT
MY RESPECT,
YOU WON'T ANSWER THAT, OKAY?
IT'S JUST GONNA
CAUSE MORE PROBLEMS.
[disconnection tone]
- HELLO?
THEY HUNG UP.
THEY HUNG UP ON ME.
HIYA, GUYS.
I COULDN'T GET THE MONEY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
- I'M IMPRESSED YOU HUNG UP.
- DID I HANG UP?
I MEANT TO HIT SPEAKER.
- OH.
YOU GOTTA HIT THE LINE FIRST.
- I'M HITTING BOTH
AT THE SAME TIME.
- THESE ARE THE LINES.
THERE'S A LINE HERE.
BUT SHE SAID--
IT'S LINE AND THEN--
- GOB, HEY.
I DON'T WANNA WAIT UNTIL DAD'S
DEAD FOR US TO GET ALONG.
narrator:
BUT IT WAS TOO LATE,
AS GEORGE SR. WOULD BE
DECLARED DEAD
WITHIN THE HOUR.
- FROM NOW ON,
WE SUPPORT EACH OTHER.
- WE START WITH A CLEAN SLATE.
- YEAH.
- WE ALMOST DID IT, THOUGH,
DIDN'T WE?
WE ALMOST PULLED IT OFF.
- NO, IT WASN'T EVEN CLOSE.
- YEAH, A LOT OF PEOPLE
GOT HURT.
- THIS WAS VERY, VERY BAD.
- NOT GREAT. NOT GREAT.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
LINDSAY FINDS OUT THE TRUE
IDENTITY OF HER HOMELESS MAN.
- LOOK. YOU'RE A REALLY NICE
CHICK, BUT I'M NOT HOMELESS.
I'M TOM JANE.
narrator: AND EVEN THOUGH
LINDSAY DOESN'T KNOW
WHO THAT IS, HEARING
THAT HE ISN'T HOMELESS
IS GOOD ENOUGH FOR HER.
- BUY ME A DRINK?
- YOU'RE REALLY SWEET, BUT, NO.
I'M TOM JANE.
narrator: AND LINDSAY,
CRUSHED AND ALONE,
FOR THE FIRST TIME
MISSES HER HUSBAND.
- TOBIAS.
- [singing]
WHEN I'M DOWN, SO DOWN
STARING AT THE GROUND
- LINDSAY, I'M--
- IS THAT GEORGE MICHAEL'S
DIAMOND CREAM?
- OH, YES, WELL,
I RAN OUT OF BLUE,
AND I COULDN'T
FIND ANYTHING ELSE.
I THINK MY NIPPLES
ARE BLEEDING, THOUGH.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO USE QUITE THIS MUCH, BUT I--
- [singing] EVERY DAY
- THAT GUY'S A JERK.
- NO, I AM.
- NO, NO, I AM.
BECAUSE I THINK I NEED TO GO TO
THE HOSPITAL RIGHT AWAY
AND SEE IF I CAN'T GET
SOME OF THIS DIAMOND DUST
VACUUMED FROM OUT OF MY LUNGS.
THIS WAY.