male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH ARRIVED AT WORK
TO FIND HIS BROTHER ADJUSTING
TO HIS NEW JOB AS PRESIDENT.
- WHAT HAVE YOU GOT THERE?
"DON'T BE AFRAID
TO MAKE A MI--"
- I'M NOT GONNA
BEAT MYSELF UP OVER THAT.
- OH.
IT WORKS.
SO, I WROTE YOUR
"MESSAGE FROM THE PRESIDENT"
ON THE SHAREHOLDERS' STATEMENT.
STARLA'S MAKING COPIES.
- DID I TELL YOU THAT SHE'D
MAKE A GREAT SECRETARY?
- YEAH, I'M NOT SO SURE THAT
HIRING HER WASN'T A MISTAKE.
- AND I'M NOT AFRAID
TO MAKE MISTAKES.
OR HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
THIS LITTLE--
DAMN IT!
MY LEGS ARE SO POWERFUL.
- UH, SO I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
WANT TO READ IT,
SEEING AS HOW YOU ARE
THE PRESIDENT NOW,
EVEN THOUGH
IT'S JUST A TITLE.
- UH, RIGHT.
YES.
WELL, WE SHOULD "CIRCUMVRENT"
UNION PENALTIES.
"CIRCUMVERATE."
- CIRCUMVENT.
MEANS TO GO AROUND.
- THE OLD REACH AROUND.
- TRUST ME.
THIS MAKES YOU
LOOK LIKE A LEADER, OKAY?
- I DON'T THINK THAT
I NEED ANY HELP WITH THAT.
[bleep] IT.
JUST LEAVE IT WHERE IT IS.
- NOW, IF YOU JUST FLIP--
- HERE ARE THE COPIES.
- OH, HEY, THESE ARE--
THESE ARE VERY SMALL.
- WHEN YOU SAID YOU WANTED
PHOTOCOPIES,
I THOUGHT THAT YOU MEANT YOU
WANTED THEM ON A PHOTO PRINTER.
- TELL YOU WHAT.
FROM NOW ON, WE'RE GONNA USE
JUST THE BIG PRINTER.
- OKAY.
YOU'RE A PERFECTIONIST.
FLASHES OF QUINCY.
narrator: STARLA CLAIMED
TO HAVE HAD A RELATIONSHIP
WITH MUSIC LEGEND QUINCY JONES.
- MR. PRESIDENT,
I'M GONNA GO LOOK INTO
SOME LEGOLAND TICKETS
FOR THE WEEKEND.
- COOL.
LET'S DO IT.
- ACTUALLY,
I JUST MEANT ME AND MY SON.
- ISN'T HE A LITTLE OLD
FOR THAT?
- NO.
SORRY, I'VE BEEN LOOKING TO GET
SOME ALONE TIME WITH HIM,
AND IT JUST HASN'T SEEMED
TO WORK OUT LATELY.
- NO PROBLEM.
I'LL JUST CALL UP
SOME OF MY FRIENDS.
- [chuckles]
- WHAT?
- WHAT FRIENDS?
- I'VE GOT FRIENDS, MICHAEL.
I JUST DON'T
TALK TO THEM BECAUSE
I WORK ALL THE TIME.
I THINK THE PLANT LADY'S
WEARING A THONG.
- MICHAEL,
THIS IS YOUR OFFICE NOW?
- YEAH.
WELL, IT'S TEMPORARY.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE SURE GOB
LOOKS LIKE HE'S IN CHARGE.
- OH, PLEASE, ALLOW ME.
I'LL JUST "CIRCUMVRENT" YOU.
- LET'S MAKE SURE WE DON'T
GIVE HIM ANY REAL POWER.
- MMM.
- SO, I GOT A CALL TODAY FROM
GENE PARMESAN, OUR PRIVATE EYE.
- HE SAID HE FOUND
SOMETHING BIG.
- WE HAVE A PRIVATE EYE, HUH?
- OH, I HIRED HIM
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO
TO FIND OUT IF YOUR FATHER
WAS CHEATING ON ME.
HE NEVER DID FIND ANYTHING.
- WELL, HE CAN'T BE
VERY GOOD, THEN.
UH, WHAT DID HE FIND?
- HE SAID HE WANTED TO
TELL US IN PERSON.
- [in an Italian accent]
DON'T GET UP.
I JUST A-FIND-A
THE SUPPLIES BECAUSE I'M A--
[drops accent]
PRIVATE DETECTIVE.
GENE PARMESAN.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
- [shrieks] GENE!
OH, GENE!
ISN'T HE THE BEST?
narrator:
GENE WAS FAR FROM THE BEST.
- THAT'S VERY IMPRESSIVE.
- THANK YOU.
- WHAT DID YOU FIND?
- OH, NOTHING.
JUST YOUR FATHER'S GETAWAY CAR.
- YOU'RE KIDDING.
narrator:
MICHAEL'S FATHER HAD USED
THE FAMILY STAIRWAY
VEHICLE TO ESCAPE FROM PRISON.
- IF I COULD FIND DAD,
I'D BE OFF THE HOOK.
I COULD BE PRESIDENT AGAIN.
WHERE IS IT?
- MEXICO.
YOU GET THE COUNTRY FOR FREE.
THE CITY--THAT'S GONNA COST YOU.
[fire alarm beeping]
- IT'S A $200 FINE.
- OH!
- I FEEL LIKE SUCH AN--
[bleep]
THE CAR IS
IN A TOWN CALLED ENCANTA.
IF YOU THINK THAT'S
WORTH MORE THAN $200,
THEN I'D REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
- ALL RIGHT, HERE.
- I'M NOT EVEN GONNA COUNT IT.
- YOU CAN LEAVE TOMORROW
AFTER MY GOING-AWAY PARTY
FOR BUSTER.
I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE
HE'S GOING INTO THE ARMY.
YOU KNOW, HE'S DOING IT
JUST TO SPITE ME.
- THEN WHY ARE YOU
THROWING HIM A PARTY?
- JUST TO SPITE HIM.
- YOU GUYS HAVE SUCH
A HEALTHY THING GOING.
OKAY, I'LL GO TO YOUR PARTY,
AND THEN I'LL GO TO MEXICO.
I GUESS THAT'LL BE
MY QUALITY TIME WITH MY SON.
- MEXICO?
- YEAH, MOM'S P.I.
FOUND THE STAIR CAR DOWN THERE.
- GENE PARMESAN?
- RIGHT HERE.
- [shrieks]
- I COUNTED IT.
COME ON.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN GOB BECAME SUSPICIOUS
THAT MICHAEL
HAD ONLY MADE HIM PRESIDENT
TO STICK HIM
WITH THE FAILING BUSINESS,
WHILE MICHAEL HIMSELF
ESCAPED TO MEXICO
TO BE WITH HIS FATHER.
SO, INSPIRED BY HIS MOTHER'S
PRIVATE DETECTIVE...
- "ICE."
narrator:
HE DECIDED TO HIRE SOMEONE
TO KEEP AN EYE
ON HIS BROTHER.
- I THINK I MIGHT HAVE SOMEONE
WHO'S GOING TO
"CIRSUMVRENT" THE LAW.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL RETURNED HOME
EAGER TO TELL HIS SON
OF THEIR TRIP.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
WHAT DO YOU SAY YOU AND I
TAKE A LITTLE ROAD TRIP
DOWN TO MEXICO TOMORROW
RIGHT AFTER BUSTER'S PARTY?
- OH, I CAN'T.
I'M MEETING ANN.
- WHO?
- ANN.
HERE, YOU TOOK
THIS PICTURE OF US
IN FRONT OF THAT BAGEL PLACE
BEFORE IT WAS BURNED DOWN.
- I GUESS I THOUGHT
SHE WAS WITH ANOTHER FAMILY.
- SHE'S KIND OF MY GIRLFRIEND.
- HER?
- DO YOU NOT LIKE HER?
- I DON'T KNOW HER.
YOU KNOW?
IT'S LIKE YOU SPEND
ALL YOUR TIME WITH HER.
IT'S LIKE YOU'RE HOGGIN' HER--
LIKE YOU'RE A LITTLE ANN HOG.
OKAY?
DON'T BE SUCH AN ANN HOG.
BUT WE'RE GONNA GO TO MEXICO.
TRY TO FIND POP-POP.
IT'LL BE AN ADVENTURE.
- WELL.
- AND 8:01.
CURTAIN HAS RISEN.
[chuckles]
- HEY, TOBIAS, I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU WERE AVAILABLE TOMORROW
TO GO DOWN TO MEXICO.
I NEED TWO DRIVERS.
- ALAS,
I HAVE TWO SHOWS TOMORROW
WHERE I'M ON STANDBY
FOR THE BLUE MAN GROUP.
MIGHT AS WELL
KEEP THIS MAKEUP ON
SINCE IT TAKES
SO [bleep] LONG TO GET OFF.
- HMM.
LINDSAY, WHAT ABOUT YOU?
- UH, CAN'T.
I HAVE A BIG DATE TOMORROW.
- YOU KNOW, THIS OPEN MARRIAGE
IS RIDICULOUS.
SOMEBODY'S GONNA GET HURT.
- THE IMPORTANT THING IS
THAT YOU GUYS DON'T
LOSE FOCUS ON YOURSELVES.
- YOU KNOW, FIRST OF ALL,
WE ARE DOING THIS FOR HER.
OKAY?
BECAUSE NEITHER ONE OF US
WANTS TO GET DIVORCED.
AND "SECOND-OF-LY,"
I KNOW YOU'RE THE BIG
MARRIAGE EXPERT--
OH, I'M SORRY.
I FORGOT.
YOUR WIFE IS DEAD.
[chuckles]
I'M SORRY,
THAT WAS 100% INAPPROPRIATE,
AND I DO APOLOGIZE PROFUSELY.
I'M--OH.
- OKAY, LOOK.
I DON'T HAVE A DATE TOMORROW.
BUT WHY CAN'T YOU ASK
GOB TO GO WITH YOU?
narrator: MICHAEL AND GOB
HAD BEEN TO MEXICO ONCE BEFORE.
- CHICLET?
CHICLET?
- YOU'RE THE CHICLET!
NOT ME!
[clucking]
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
IN MEXICAN CULTURE,
THIS WAS A MUCH MORE
INFLAMMATORY GESTURE.
- [clucking]
- HEY, HEY.
I JUST THINK YOU AND I
WOULD HAVE A LOT MORE FUN.
PLUS, YOU CAN BRING MAEBY.
- YOU KNOW,
I'VE SENSED HER FEELING
A LITTLE LEFT OUT LATELY.
narrator: AND THE NEXT MORNING,
THE FAMILY MET AT BUSTER'S
SEND-OFF PARTY,
WHERE LUCILLE WAS NOT KEEPING
HER FEELINGS HIDDEN.
- A CAMCORDER.
- THAT'S SO YOU CAN
VIDEOTAPE IT
WHEN THEY PUT YOU
IN A NAKED PYRAMID
AND POINT TO
YOUR CHARLIE BROWNS.
- I OUGHT TO POINT TO
UNCLE OSCAR'S CHARLIE BROWNS
NEXT TIME YOU'RE
ON TOP OF HIM, MOTHER.
- HE'S MOVING OUT.
YOU SEE HOW HE TREATS ME?
JUST BECAUSE HE THINKS
I'M HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH THE BOY'S UNCLE.
- YES,
AND SHE'S NOT HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH THE BOY'S...UNCLE.
- IT'S TOO LATE FOR APOLOGIES.
I'M GOING TO THE ARMY.
GET ME OUT.
YOU'VE GOT TO GET ME OUT.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
I'M HEADED DOWN TO MEXICO
TO TRY TO FIND DAD,
BUT WHEN I GET BACK, MAYBE WE'LL
TRY TO FIGURE SOMETHING OUT.
narrator:
AND THAT'S WHEN BUSTER DECIDED
TO SNEAK INTO MEXICO
TO AVOID THE SERVICE.
- NO, NO, I THINK IT'LL
BE WORKED OUT BY THEN.
[giggles]
- WHAT WAS THAT ALL ABOUT?
- I THINK BUSTER'S GONNA
ESCAPE TO MEXICO.
DID THE SECRETARY NOT GIVE YOU
THE PICTURE FOR DAD?
I NEED THAT TO SHOW
THE PEOPLE DOWN THERE.
- UH, YEAH,
SHE BROUGHT THAT OVER.
- WELL, THIS,
UH, IS A BLUEPRINT...
OF DAD'S FACE.
SHE USED THE BIG PRINTER.
I'LL GIVE HER THAT.
LET'S GO.
- NOT SO FAST.
GOB, WHO IS THAT MAN
ON THE COUCH?
- OH, THAT GUY?
HE'S MY FRIEND.
- YOU DON'T HAVE ANY FRIENDS.
- I HAVE LOTS OF FRIENDS,
LINDSAY.
narrator: IN FACT,
THE MAN WAS ICE, A BOUNTY HUNTER
THAT GOB HIRED
TO FOLLOW MICHAEL.
- ICE MAY BE MY BEST FRIEND.
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
- HE'S MOVING.
- FUN PARTY, HUH?
- NO, NO, IT ISN'T.
LET'S GO DOWN TO MEXICO.
- ALL RIGHT.
LET ME GRAB ANN REAL QUICK.
- WHAT--ANN'S HERE?
- YEAH, I INVITED HER.
YOU--YOU SAID YOU WANTED
TO SPEND SOME TIME WITH HER.
YOU SAID I WAS BEING AN ANN HOG.
- ANN HOG'S COMING?
I MEAN, I THOUGHT IT WAS JUST...
- IT'S JUST ANN.
- GONNA BE, LIKE, THE TWO OF US.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
JUST LOAD HER UP IN THE CAR.
- ALL RIGHT.
- LUPE, THAT SWEATER'S
NOT A TAKE-HOME.
MICHAEL, GIVE HER A RIDE HOME.
- I'M GONNA HAVE TO START
PUTTING PEOPLE IN THE TRUNK.
narrator:
IN FACT, AT THAT MOMENT,
BUSTER WAS CLIMBING
INTO THE TRUNK.
- MOTHER, WHEN YOU SEE
THIS VIDEOTAPE,
YOU'LL KNOW THAT I LEFT.
NOT OUT OF COWARDICE,
BUT OUT OF--
[yawns] OH, MAN.
IT'S TIRING IN HERE.
OH.
narrator:
SIX MINUTES LATER,
MICHAEL DROPPED OFF
HIS MOTHER'S HOUSEKEEPER.
- MEXICO.
narrator:
IN FACT, HE WAS IN SANTA ANA,
A TOWN SIX MINUTES INLAND
FROM HIS OWN.
BUT THE COMBINATION
OF LOSING HIS GLASSES
AND BREATHING
CARBON MONOXIDE
HAD IMPAIRED BUSTER'S JUDGMENT.
- OH, THIS SHALL KEEP ME SAFE
FROM THE HOT MEXICAN SUN.
- EXCUSE ME.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- [in a Mexican accent] I'M
TRYING TO FIND A PLACE TO LIVE.
- AY.
[speaking Spanish]
narrator: MICHAEL
WAS HEADING DOWN TO MEXICO
TO FIND HIS FUGITIVE FATHER.
- CAN YOU BELIEVE THIS?
THIS IS MY TRIP WITH MY SON,
AND HE'S TOO BUSY
WHISPERING SECRETS TO ANN
TO SAY ONE WORD TO ME.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- NOTHING.
WE'RE NOT
WHISPERING SECRETS UP HERE.
- HEY, CHECK OUT
WHO'S ON THAT HOG
IN THE REARVIEW MIRROR.
- GEORGE MICHAEL!
- WHAT?
- TWENTY MILES TO LEGOLAND.
[rings]
- THE ICE.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
- STILL ON HIS TAIL,
ABOUT 20 MILES FROM LEGOLAND.
- GO GET HIM, FRIEND.
- YOU'RE NOT MY FRIEND.
YOU'RE A CLIENT.
narrator: GOB REALIZED
THAT PERHAPS HE REALLY DIDN'T
HAVE ANY FRIENDS.
- AND LUCILLE SENT HERS AWAY.
BUSTER, OSCAR'S LEAVING.
YOU WIN.
- BUSTER GET IN TRUNK
OF CAR.
- SO HE'S NOT GOING
TO THE ARMY.
HE MUST HAVE HAD MICHAEL
SNEAK HIM INTO MEXICO.
OH, THANK GOD.
- IT'S BETTER THIS WAY.
both: MMM.
[smooching]
- I'LL GO UNPACK.
- HERE'S SOME MONEY.
GO SEE A STAR WAR.
[knocking]
WHO IS IT?
- UH, YOUR SON.
- WHAT?
- I WAS LOOKING FOR BUSTER.
- HE'S NOT HERE.
- UH, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I MEAN, DO YOU WANT TO GO OUT?
- WHY ARE YOU TRYING
TO GET ME OUT OF THE HOUSE?
- I JUST THOUGHT
THAT WE COULD HANG OUT.
[door creaking]
narrator:
LUCILLE WAS SUSPICIOUS
THAT GOB WAS UP TO
SOME SORT OF POWER GRAB.
- GENE PARMESAN?
LUCILLE BLUTH.
MY SON IS TRYING
TO GET ME OUT OF MY HOUSE.
I THINK HE MAY BE
UP TO SOMETHING.
[knocking]
OH, HOLD ON.
THAT'S PROBABLY HIM.
GENE?
IT'S JUST SOME IDIOT
WITH BALLOONS.
- OH, IS IT?
- [shrieks] I KNEW IT!
I WANT YOU TO KEEP AN EYE
ON MY SON GOB.
narrator: AND BUSTER WAS
FINDING HIMSELF RIGHT AT HOME.
- OH, MY GOD, I USED TO HAVE
A SHIRT JUST LIKE THAT.
narrator:
IT WAS BUSTER'S OLD SHIRT.
LUCILLE HAD GIVEN IT TO LUPE.
- AND THE HAND CHAIR.
I HAD ONE IN MY ROOM.
I WONDER WHERE THAT WENT.
narrator: IT WENT RIGHT THERE.
- I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D MISS A HAND SO MUCH.
YOU PEOPLE ARE JUST LIKE ME.
[chuckles]
narrator:
MEANWHILE, IN THE REAL MEXICO,
MICHAEL HAD FOUND
THE STAIR CAR.
- YEP, THERE IT IS.
narrator: AND MICHAEL SET ABOUT
FINDING HIS FATHER.
- OH, YEAH, SURE, SENOR.
NO PROBLEM.
WHEN DO YOU
WANT US TO START BUILDING?
- THANK YOU.
GRACIAS.
- HEY, DAD, DAD.
- YEAH.
- SO WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF ANN SO FAR?
- OH, ANN?
I-I JUST--
YOU KNOW, I-I BARELY KNOW HER.
YOU KNOW?
NEITHER OF US DO.
SHE'S JUST REALLY SOME GIRL
AS FAR AS WE'RE CONCERNED.
RIGHT?
I-I-I'M DETERMINED
TO GET TO KNOW HER, THOUGH.
- YEAH.
- OKAY?
- OKAY, I HAVE AN IDEA.
WHEN WE GO BACK,
WHY DON'T JUST THE TWO OF YOU GO
BACK IN THE STAIR CAR TOGETHER?
- WELL, THAT'S NO FUN.
FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, YOU GUYS--
YOU GUYS SHOULD BE TOGETHER.
- OH--
- OR MAYBE JUST YOU AND ME.
IF YOU'D RATHER.
- YEAH.
- OR ME AND ANN--
- GREAT, YES, OKAY.
I'LL TELL MAEBY
THAT I'LL BE GOING BACK
WITH HER AND AUNT LINDSAY--
GREAT.
- NO, NO, NO, WAIT.
LET'S--LET'S KEEP
LOOKING FOR POP-POP.
YOU KNOW?
- OH, OKAY.
- MAYBE SOMEBODY IN THE CHURCH
WILL KNOW SOMETHING.
narrator: IN FACT,
GEORGE SR. WAS IN THE CHURCH,
WHERE HE WAS MOURNED
BY HIS LONGTIME ASSISTANT
AND ACCOMPLICE
TO HIS ESCAPE, KITTY,
AS ONLY A FEW DAYS EARLIER,
HE'D BEEN DECLARED DEAD.
[gunshot]
BUT BEFORE MICHAEL
COULD GO INSIDE THE CHURCH--
- [yelling]
- HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I KNOW YOU.
YOU'RE GOB'S FRIEND.
- NOT FRIEND.
BOUNTY HUNTER.
- GENE?
THERE'S NO WAY
YOU'RE THAT GOOD.
- NAME'S ICE.
GOB HIRED ME TO STOP YOU
FROM FLEEING THE COUNTRY.
- COME--WHAT?
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
I'M NOT FLEEING THE COUNTRY.
I'M HERE LOOKING FOR MY FATHER.
BUT YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY
BETTER AT THIS KIND OF THING,
SO I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'M GONNA CONTINUE PAYING YOU
TO FIND MY FATHER.
YOU CAN ALSO COLLECT
THE REAL BOUNTY ON HIS HEAD.
- NICE DECK.
IS THIS WHERE YOU SAW HIM LAST?
- NO, THIS--
THAT'S ACTUALLY HIM.
HE'S JUST--HE'S MUCH
SMALLER IN REAL LIFE.
- I CAN SEE THAT'S A MAN.
I'LL FIND HIM.
- LUCKY.
- WHAT DID HE SAY?
DID HE ASK ABOUT ME?
I-I CAN'T BELIEVE HE FOLLOWED US
ALL THE WAY TO MEXICO.
- UH, THAT'S A BOUNTY HUNTER,
AND, UH, HE'S ON THE CASE,
SO WE CAN ALL HEAD HOME.
- SO HE'S NOT INTERESTED IN ME?
- NOT UNLESS
YOU KNOW WHERE DAD IS.
GEORGE MICHAEL.
- OH, HI, DAD.
YEAH.
THEY THINK YOU'RE IN MEXICO.
I'LL SEE YOU WHEN I GET HOME.
YE--OH, YES.
THANK YOU.
NO, I FOUND
MY BIRTH CONTROL PILLS.
THANKS FOR ASKING, DAD.
narrator: MAEBY HAD
HAD ENOUGH OF HER MOTHER
AND DECIDED TO GO BACK
WITH MICHAEL.
- I'M SO SICK OF HER.
THE LAME FLIRTING.
narrator: MICHAEL, OF COURSE,
THOUGHT MAEBY
WAS REFERRING TO ANN.
- YOU KNOW, I THINK
HE'S GONNA GET SICK OF HER
BEFORE IT GOES TOO FAR.
- OF COURSE HE WILL.
SHE'S A CHILD.
- WELL, THAT--THAT PART'S
NOT REALLY HER FAULT.
I-I JUST HATE TO SEE HIM
WASTING HIS TIME, YOU KNOW?
- LET'S JUST GO.
I'LL BE IN YOUR CAR.
- WELL, IS GEORGE MICHAEL
OKAY WITH THAT?
- IT'S FINE.
JUST DRIVE.
narrator: AT NO POINT
WERE MICHAEL AND MAEBY
TALKING ABOUT THE SAME PERSON.
AND THERE WERE ONLY
FOUR PEOPLE IN THEIR GROUP.
- AND IT'S NOT A RACE THING.
- YEAH,
WHOEVER GETS THERE FIRST.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL
LEFT WITH HIS NIECE,
FOLLOWED BY HIS SISTER
AND HIS SON,
FOLLOWED BY THE BOUNTY HUNTER.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THIS LEFT THE GIRL
MICHAEL WAS DETERMIND
TO GET TO KNOW ALONE IN MEXICO.
MEANWHILE,
BUSTER WAS ADAPTING TO LIFE
IN WHAT HE THOUGHT
WAS MEXICO, BUT WAS IN FACT
A TOWN SO CLOSE TO HOME
THAT THEY SHARED A PAPERBOY.
- I KNOW THAT GUY.
HEY, WHERE'S YOUR MOTHER?
- OH, I LOVE THIS WAY OF LIFE.
THIS IS WHERE I BELONG.
I LOVE BEING MEXICAN.
- WE MUST WORK NOW, AMIGO.
ADIOS.
- OH, NO, NO.
I'M GOING WITH YOU.
[in a Mexican accent]
I AM ONE OF YOU NOW, SI?
narrator: AND MICHAEL,
ON HIS WAY BACK HOME,
BONDED WITH MAEBY.
- I MEAN, WHY DOES EVERYONE
HAVE TO DATE ANYWAYS?
- RIGHT, I MEAN,
ISN'T FAMILY ENOUGH FOR PEOPLE?
AND, YOU KNOW,
NOT TO FEEL SORRY FOR MYSELF,
BUT IT'S LIKE
I'M BEING FORGOTTEN HERE.
narrator: AND SOON
THEY ALL ARRIVED AT HOME.
- HEY, YOU'RE HERE ALREADY.
- YEAH, WE WON.
- SO, UH, YOU GUYS HAVE
A GOOD TALK?
- YEAH.
GREAT TALK.
THAT COUSIN OF YOURS
IS A HELL OF A GIRL.
IT'S TOO BAD YOU CAN'T DATE HER.
- NO.
I MEANT--
WAIT, YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
NOTHING.
NO, I WAS
TALKING ABOUT ANN.
WHAT DID YOU THINK OF HER?
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD JUST DISCOVERED
HE'D LEFT
HIS SON'S GIRLFRIEND IN MEXICO.
- SHE'S GONNA BE FINE.
WE JUST GOT TO BEAT THE SUN.
- HEY, YOU THINK I'M HAPPY
ABOUT THIS?
BUT, HEY, WE ARE GETTING
THAT TRIP TOGETHER
WE WANTED, THOUGH, HUH?
AND LOOK.
TWO EXITS TO LEGOLAND.
- I JUST WANT TO FIND ANN.
- THAT'S MY WHOLE THING TOO.
narrator: AND GOB WAS
STILL SEARCHING FOR A FRIEND.
- SHOW TONIGHT?
- WELL, I WON'T KNOW OFFICIALLY
UNTIL 8:01,
BUT I FIGURED
IF I BLUE MYSELF EARLY,
I'D BE NICE AND RELAXED
FOR A 9:00 DINNER RESERVATION.
[chuckles]
AND IF YOU'D LIKE, I CAN MAKE
THAT RESERVATION FOR--
- LOOKING FOR SOME COMPANY OR--
- I SURE AM.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE GONNA SCARE AWAY THE ICE.
- ICE?
ICE IS OUT THERE?
WHERE'S MICHAEL?
- HE WENT BACK TO MEXICO.
- HMM, I KNEW
HE WAS TRYING TO FLEE.
- WHERE THE HELL DID HE GO?
- [yells]
- WHOA!
- ICE, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- GEORGE BLUTH,
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
- THAT'S NOT MY FATHER.
- WELL, ACCORDING TO
MY PHOTOGRAPH, IT IS.
- [laughs]
IT'S AN HONEST MISTAKE.
ALSO, I THINK YOUR KNEE
IS ON MY HEART.
- HE'S MY HUSBAND.
MY FATHER IS PROBABLY
STILL IN MEXICO.
I WAS JUST HOPING
TO HAVE SEX WITH YOU.
- WHY AM I NOT BLACKING OUT?
- HE SET ME UP.
MICHAEL SET ME UP.
- HEY, WHO WANTS TO GO
TO THE HOSPITAL?
narrator: AND BUSTER WENT
TO HIS JOB AS A DISHWASHER.
- THIS IS GREAT.
WE'RE LIKE SLAVE BUDDIES.
[chuckles]
OH.
narrator: SOON,
THE GUYS ARRIVED IN MEXICO
AND SPLIT UP TO FIND ANN.
- ANN?
ANN?
OH, THANK GOD,
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
- MR. BLUTH?
ANN, OH, THANK GOD,
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
UH, YOU ARE ANN, RIGHT?
YES, OF COURSE YOU ARE.
- ANN, OH, MY--
- IT IS--WE GOT HER.
OKAY, LET'S GO AHEAD AND LOAD UP
IN THE TRUCK.
I THINK WE'RE
CRASHING SOME POOR GUY'S WAKE.
- MICHAEL, MICHAEL, MICHAEL!
- GOB?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- FLEEING THE COUNTRY?
YOU BASTARD.
- NO.
I'M STILL NOT FLEEING, OKAY?
I'M JUST HERE TO PICK UP
MY SON'S GIRLFRIEND.
SHE RAN OFF THE LAST TIME
WE WERE LEAVING.
- ACTUALLY, I WAS SITTING
RIGHT THERE THE WHOLE TIME.
- YEAH?
WAY TO PLANT, ANN.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, UH, LISTEN.
WHY DON'T YOU AND PLANT
JUST WAIT IN THE STAIR CAR.
I'M GONNA
FINISH UP HERE WITH GOB.
- WHAT A SCARE.
- WHAT IS THAT?
THAT'S HIS GIRLFRIEND?
- YEAH.
- WHAT, IS SHE FUNNY
OR SOMETHING?
- DON'T--DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
WHY DO YOU KEEP THINKING
THAT I'M RUNNING AWAY?
- I MEAN,
IT IS KIND OF SUSPICIOUS
YOU DIDN'T EVEN ASK ME
TO DRIVE DOWN HERE WITH YOU.
- WELL, THE ONLY REASON
I DIDN'T ASK YOU TO COME WITH US
IS BECAUSE OF
YOUR CHICKEN IMPRESSION.
- YEAH, WE SURE DID GET IN A LOT
OF TROUBLE FOR THAT LAST TIME.
DIDN'T WE?
- OH, YEAH.
- I WAS ALL--
[clucking]
- HEY, NO.
YOU'RE DOING IT AGAIN.
- [yelling]
- GET OFF HIM.
HE DOESN'T KNOW WHAT HE'S DOING.
HE'S AMERICAN.
- AMERICANO, EH?
JUST LIKE ME.
GENE PARMESAN.
HOW YOU DOING?
- GENE!
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
- WELL, YOUR MOTHER SENT ME
TO FIND YOU.
SHE WAS WORRIED YOU WERE
UP TO SOMETHING.
- I WAS JUST LOOKING
FOR A FRIEND.
- WHAT?
- YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT, MICHAEL.
I WENT TO OUR MOTHER BECAUSE
I DON'T HAVE ANY FRIENDS.
- OH, THAT'S FUNNY.
- THANK YOU.
GENE, CAN I JUST HAVE
A PRIVATE MOMENT, PLEASE?
- OKAY.
YOU'RE ON THE CLOCK.
- THANK YOU.
GOB, WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
IF ANYBODY NEEDS A FRIEND
RIGHT NOW, IT'S ME.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW,
MY SON'S FURIOUS AT ME,
AND HE SPENDS ALL OF HIS
FREE TIME WITH THIS GIRL
THAT, FRANKLY,
I'M NOT THAT CRAZY ABOUT.
- NOT CRAZY ABOUT?
OR NOT CRAZY ABOUT
YOUR SON GROWING UP?
- UH--MAYBE--MAYBE
YOU'RE RIGHT ABOUT THAT.
AND I REALLY HAVEN'T
GOTTEN TO KNOW HER.
I'VE BEEN
A LITTLE SELFISH, SO--
SEE?
YOU ARE A FRIEND.
YOU KNOW, I'M--I'M ALWAYS
GONNA LOOK OUT FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT?
AND YOU'RE ALWAYS GONNA
LOOK OUT FOR ME.
- [yells]
- SORRY.
I DID SEE HIM COMING.
IT'S JUST,
I KIND OF WANTED TO SEE
WHERE YOU WERE GOING
WITH THAT.
- WHERE'S UNCLE GOB?
- WELL, I GAVE
THE BOUNTY HUNTER AND THE P.I.
A FEW EXTRA BUCKS
TO BE HIS FRIENDS
FOR THE WEEKEND--
WHILE THE THREE OF THEM
ARE LOOKING FOR MY FATHER.
AND I WANT TO GET TO KNOW
A NEW FRIEND TOO.
ANN, WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT YOURSELF?
[engine turns over]
narrator:
THE NEXT DAY, BUSTER WAS HAPPY.
AND HE DECIDED TO NEVER
GO HOME AGAIN.
- [humming]
DELIVERY FROM THE KITCHEN.
narrator: BUT UNFORTUNATELY,
HE WAS ALREADY THERE.
- [gasps] MOTHER!
- BUSTER!
I THOUGHT YOU WERE IN MEXICO.
- SO DID I!
- OH!
- narrator: AND THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL RETURNED TO WORK,
KNOWING A LITTLE MORE
ABOUT HIS SON'S GIRLFRIEND.
- YOU TELL ANN
TO MAKE SURE SHE STUDIES
FOR MR. MASON'S
ALGEBRA II TEST TOMORROW,
AND TELL HER TO MAKE SURE
THAT KIM CHO DOESN'T
CHEAT OFF HER THIS TIME.
- WOW.
YOU REALLY GOT TO KNOW HER.
- WELL, WE DID SPEND THREE HOURS
TOGETHER IN THAT CAR RIDE.
- SO, WHAT'D YOU THINK?
- I DON'T LIKE HER.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
BUSTER RECLAIMS
HIS FAVORITE CHAIR.
- [gasps]
- BUT THE VICTORY
IS SHORT-LIVED.
- MAKE LOVE
IN YOUR OWN HAND, MOTHER!
narrator: AND TOBIAS GETS
MEDICAL ATTENTION.
- OH, THANK GOD!
A NEW DOCTOR.
FINALLY WE CAN GET
A STRAIGHT ANSWER IN THIS PLACE.
- UH, I'VE GOT SOME BAD NEWS.
I'M GENE PARMESAN.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
- [shrieks] HE GOT ME AGAIN!
[laughs]
- BUT I DID OVERHEAR
THAT HE'S BLEEDING INTERNALLY.