[narrator]
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS ADJUSTING TO HIS
NEW POSITION AS VICE PRESIDENT,
WHICH MEANT DOING THE WORK OF
THE PRESIDENT, HIS BROTHER GOB.
- MICHAEL.
- HEY.
- SO, DID YOU SEE
THE NEW POOF?
- HIS NAME'S GARY, AND WE DON'T
NEED ANY MORE LAWSUITS.
- NO, I WAS TALKING
ABOUT THE MAGAZINE--
WAIT.
GARY'S GAY?
- YEAH.
- UH-OH. HE'S GONNA THINK
I WAS COMING ON TO HIM.
YOU'VE GOT A NICE MOUTH.
I'D KILL FOR THAT ASS.
OKAY, THE CHAIR'S
NOT DOING IT NOW,
BUT LATELY
IT'S BEEN GIVING OUT
AS SOON AS I LEAN BACK.
ANYWAY, I WAS TALKING
ABOUT POOF MAGAZINE,
THE MAGAZINE FOR MAGICIANS.
THIS GUY TONY WONDER BAKES
HIMSELF INTO A LOAF OF BREAD AND
POPS OUT OF A GIANT SANDWICH...
TO FEED THE TROOPS.
I HAD THAT IDEA
10 MONTHS AGO.
- YOU HAD THAT IDEA?
- WELL, BASICALLY.
I WAS GONNA BOIL MYSELF ALIVE
INTO A CHOWDER AND THEN BE
LADLED INTO A GIANT CAULDRON...
TO ENTERTAIN
AND FEED THE FIREMEN.
- THAT'S PRETTY CLOSE.
- I SHOULD BE IN THIS POOF!
[phone rings]
- MICHAEL BLUTH.
- HE FOUND HIM.
ICE FOUND YOUR FATHER.
[narrator]
MICHAEL HAD RECENTLY HAD HIRED
A BOUNTY HUNTER...
TO TRACK DOWN
HIS FUGITIVE FATHER.
- WH-WHERE?
- HE'S COMING OVER HERE AT 5:00
TO TELL US.
BUT HE WANTS
TO GET PAID FIRST.
- DAD GOES BACK TO JAIL,
I CAN BE CLEARED,
I CAN BE PRESIDENT AGAIN.
- AND I'M HALFWAY TO
GETTING OUT OF THIS OFFICE AND
INTO A STEAMING BOWL OF SOUP.
- EVERYBODY WINS.
- YEAH.
- OSCAR, CLOSE IT.
YOU LOOK LIKE THE WINDOW
OF A BUTCHER SHOP.
THANK GOD I CAN
FINALLY GET RID OF HIM.
- I'LL SEE YOU AT 5:00, MOM.
[narrator]
MICHAEL THEN HEADED DOWN
TO THE FROZEN BANANA STAND...
WHERE HIS SON
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE WORKING.
- IT JUST SEEMS LIKE EVERY TIME
WE WANNA BE TOGETHER,
YOUR FATHER COMES ALONG--
- HEY, GUYS. WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHY'S THE BANANA STAND CLOSED?
- OH, ANN CAME TO SEE ME,
SO I THOUGHT I'D TAKE
A LITTLE BREAK.
CAN WE TALK ABOUT THIS LATER?
- SURE. NO PROBLEM.
JUST, LET'S KEEP
THE PHONE ON.
OKAY, PAL? GREAT.
HEY, YOU.
[beep]
- SEE? THAT'S A PERFECT
EXAMPLE OF HOW YOUR FATHER'S
ALWAYS INTERRUP--
[vibrating]
- I'M SORRY.
[beep]
HELLO.
- HEY, BUDDY.
THEY FOUND YOUR GRANDFATHER.
THAT'S WHAT
I WANTED TO TELL YOU.
- THAT'S GREAT.
- I DIDN'T WANNA SAY THAT
WHEN YOU WERE TALKING TO EGG.
- I'M STILL TALKING WITH ANN.
- OH, SHE'S STILL GOIN'?
LISTEN, I'LL TALK TO YOU LATER.
I'M VERY EXCITED.
- [mutters]
THAT'S GOOD.
[beep]
- I THINK WE SHOULD BREAK UP.
- [coughing sob]
[narrator]
THE BOUNTY HUNTER, MEANWHILE,
WAS EAGER TO IMPRESS
THE FAMILY ATTORNEY.
- I CANNOT BELIEVE
THAT YOU MADE THESE.
[narrator]
INDEED, ICE HAD ALWAYS
BOUNTY-HUNTED
TO SUPPORT HIS FIRST LOVE--
PARTY-PLANNING.
AND LINDSAY
WAS STILL HOPING
TO SCORE A DATE WITH HIM.
- I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'D BE INTERESTED IN
CATERING AN AFFAIR WITH ME.
- WELL, WHEN YOU GET
A FULL GUEST LIST,
LET ME KNOW.
- WHY CAN'T I DO THIS
ANYMORE?
- THAT'S GOT TO BOTHER YOU,
HUH, DAD?
I MEAN, SHE'S FLIRTING
RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
- HMM?
OH! NO.
I AM SURPRISED, THOUGH,
THAT SHE'S GOING AFTER SOMEBODY
SO SIMILAR TO MY OWN TYPE.
BUT I SUPPOSE WE ALL DO EXPOSE
OUR INNER DESIRES, DON'T WE?
- I THINK YOU JUST DID.
- NO, I DIDN'T.
- IS THERE ANY WAY
I CAN DIVORCE THEM?
- OH, SURE.
IT'S CALLED EMANCIPATION.
BUT YOU'VE GOT TO PROVE
THAT YOU'RE LIVING
IN AN UNSTABLE ENVIRONMENT.
- BOTH MY PARENTS ARE TRYING
TO HAVE AFFAIRS.
OF COURSE,
THEY HAVEN'T SUCCEEDED YET.
- IF THEY DO, I COULD HAVE YOU
OUT OF THIS HOUSE,
ON THE STREET, IN A MONTH.
- SWEET!
- MM-HMM.
[narrator]
SOON, MICHAEL ARRIVED,
AND ICE BEGAN HIS PRESENTATION.
- WHEN WORD GOT OUT
THAT HE WAS BUILDING HOUSES
FOR SADDAM HUSSEIN,
HE ESCAPED TO MEXICO WHERE,
AS YOU KNOW, HE WAS ARRESTED
AND INTERRED IN A LOCAL PRISON.
UNTIL HE WAS KILLED
BY THIS GUARD.
BODY WAS HELD FOR SIX DAYS
WITHIN THE PRISON WALLS WHEN--
- I'M SORRY--
HE KILLED A GUARD?
- NO, THE GUARD KILLED HIM.
HE'S DEAD.
BURIED IN MEXICO.
- [screams]
- UH, H-HOLD ON.
HOW DO WE KNOW THIS IS TRUE?
- BECAUSE I HAVE HERE
HIS DENTAL RECORDS,
HIS DEATH CERTIFICATE,
AND A POLITICAL CARTOON
FROM A LEADING
MEXICAN PUBLICATION.
OKAY, AGAIN,
I'M A CATERER,
SO IF YOU DO HAVE
ANY FAMILY EVENTS--
WEDDINGS...WAKES--
I'LL LEAVE MY CARD.
- IS IT TRUE?
IS HE REALLY GONE?
- OW.
- JUST CHECKING.
- THESE ARE HIS TEETH.
HE HAD SUCH PERFECT TEETH.
IT WAS THAT GLISTEN.
- HE SWORE BY THAT GLISTEN.
- I CAN STILL HEAR HIM NOW:
"WHO LEFT THE CAP
OFF MY-- [bleep] GLISTEN?"
- IT'S ALL HITTING ME NOW.
THIS IS REALLY HAPPENING.
ALL THIS
AWFUL FUNERAL STUFF!
THE WILL.
WE HAVE TO GET THE WILL.
I DON'T KNOW
IF ENOUGH TIME HAS PASSED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
IS IT IN YOUR CAR, BARRY?
I'M GONNA THROW UP!
CHECK THE CAR, BARRY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING!
- THE WILL IS NOT HERE.
THE WILL IS AT MY OFFICE,
NEXT TO THE HOT PLATE
WITH THE FRAYED WIRES.
I DIDN'T, UH--
IT WASN'T--
[narrator]
IN FACT, BARRY HAD LOST
GEORGE SR.'s WILL.
- HOW DID I GET HERE?
OH, MY GOD, LUCILLE.
HE IS GONE!
- WE HAVE TO HAVE A WAKE.
[narrator]
MAEBY WAS UPSET, BUT SAW
A CHANCE TO FIX UP HER MOTHER.
- MAYBE WE COULD GET ICE
TO CATER IT OR SOMETHING--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING!
- WE DON'T EVEN HAVE A BODY.
- I WILL BE MY FATHER'S BODY.
I'LL BE THE ONE BURIED.
BECAUSE HE LOVED MAGIC
SO VERY MUCH.
-I DON'T THINK GOB
KNOWS WHAT HE'S SAYING.
- I KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT I'M SAYING.
I WILL BE BURIED
IN MY FATHER'S PLACE,
AND THEN, ONE WEEK LATER,
I WILL EMERGE FROM THE GRAVE..
IN ONE OF
THE GREATEST ILLUSIONS EVER!
- THIS ABOUT GETTING INTO POOF?
- I MEAN, HOW DOES THAT
NOT GET ME A COVER?
[keys jingling]
- BUSTER!
WE CAN'T TELL HIM ABOUT THIS!
- I THINK THE BOY'S
BEEN LIED TO ENOUGH.
- YOU WEREN'T HERE
FOR THE PARAKEET, OSCAR.
[narrator]
AS A CHILD, BUSTER HAD
A BELOVED PARAKEET...
WHO, AFTER LANDING ON
THEIR HOUSEKEEPER ROSA'S WIG,
FLEW AWAY...
WHEN SHE TOOK OUT THE TRASH
AND INTO A TRANSFORMER.
[electrical zap]
WHEN BUSTER FOUND OUT,
HE DESTROYED
THE FAMILY'S KITCHEN,
BELIEVING THIS TO BE
WHERE ROSA LIVED.
- WHOA.
- WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HOME?
- THE ARMY HAD HALF A DAY.
ARE YOU GUYS
PLANNING A PARTY?
- YES.
IT'S YOUR FATHER'S BIRTHDAY,
WHICH, COINCIDENTALLY, IS...
MY BIRTHDAY.
- BECAUSE YOU'RE TWINS.
[chuckles]
WELL, I'VE GOT
SOME SHOPPING TO DO.
[laughing]
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
HAD JUST BEEN BROKEN UP WITH
BY HIS FIRST GIRLFRIEND...
AND WAS ON HIS WAY HOME.
AND HE WENT TO HIS FATHER
FOR COMFORT.
- DAD?
- I'VE GOT SOME BAD NEWS.
- WHAT? WHAT?
IS ANN TELLING EVERYONE?
- IT'S YOUR GRANDFATHER.
APPARENTLY, HE'S DEAD.
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- YEAH.
YEAH, I THINK SO.
UH, I'M SORRY.
WHAT WERE YOU SAYING ABOUT ANN?
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL
DIDN'T WANT TO BURDEN HIS FATHER
WITH HIS BREAK-UP.
- NOTHING. I JUST--
I BROKE UP WITH HER.
IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
- REALLY?
- YEAH.
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- ME? I'M GREAT.
- YEAH?
- I'M GREAT.
- GOOD. YEAH.
SHE WASN'T FOR US.
- NO, SHE'S--
SHE'S A GREAT GIRL.
- FOR THOSE OTHER GUYS.
- YOU THINK THERE ARE
OTHER GUYS?
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
COME HERE.
- HEY, BROTHER.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME?
- BUSTER, YEAH.
I NEED YOU TO HELP ME WITH
THIS ILLUSION I'M WORKING ON.
- OH, FOR DAD'S BIRTHDAY.
- YEAH.
FOR DAD'S BIRTHDAY.
SO, LOOK, I'M GONNA
GET IN THIS COFFIN.
WHAT I'M GONNA NEED YOU TO DO
IS TO SPIN IT AROUND...
TO SHOW EVERYBODY
THAT THERE'S NO TRAP DOOR.
THEN I'M GONNA ESCAPE
OUT THE TRAP DOOR.
- OOH!
- YOU CLOSE THE TRAP DOOR,
BRING IN THE PALLBEARERS
AND BURY AN EMPTY BOX.
- SO IT'S A HOAX.
BUT WHY ARE YOU
DOING A COFFIN TRICK
ON DAD'S BIRTHDAY?
- BLACK HUMOR.
SAY, "HEY, DAD, LOOK AT YOU.
YOU'RE... A YEAR OLDER...
AND A YEAR CLOSER TO DEATH."
- OH, YEAH,
I GUESS THAT'S KINDA FUNNY.
OKAY, BUT YOU HAVE TO
DO A FAVOR FOR ME.
I'M NOT REALLY IN THE ARMY,
AND I TOLD MOM I WAS,
BUT I CAN'T GO
TO A FAMILY EVENT
WITHOUT AN ARMY UNIFORM.
- OH, YEAH.
I USED TO BE A STRIPPER.
- STRIPPERS DON'T WEAR CLOTHES.
- NOT AT THE END OF THE SHOW.
- YOU CAN WEAR STRIPPER CLOTHES
WHEN YOU'RE NOT STRIPPING?
- YOU TELL ME.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL WENT FOR A WALK
IN THE ADJOINING LOT...
TO GRIEVE BOTH LOSSES
IN PRIVATE,
AND HE MADE
AN INTERESTING DISCOVERY.
- POP-POP?
- HIDE ME.
DON'T TURN IN POP-POP.
HELP POP-POP.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL
SNUCK HIS GRANDFATHER INTO THE
ATTIC AND HELPED HIM CLEAN UP.
- WOW, THEY'RE PERFECT.
- YEARS OF BRUSHING
WITH GLISTEN.
LISTEN, YOU CAN'T
TELL ANYBODY I'M UP HERE.
YOU HAVE TO PROTECT ME.
- YEAH, I KNOW. I JUST--
I CAN'T NOT TELL MY FATHER.
- I'M YOUR GRANDFATHER.
I WENT THROUGH HELL TO GET HERE.
[narrator]
HE HAD.
AFTER BEING ARRESTED,
HE FOUND A LOOPHOLE
IN THE MEXICAN JUDICIAL SYSTEM.
- I HAVE, UH--
I HAVE MONEY.
[narrator]
THE MEXICAN AUTHORITIES...
EVEN ATTEMPTED
TO FAKE HIS FUNERAL,
ALTHOUGH IT WAS
A LESS-THAN-PERFECT DECEPTION.
[chattering, shouting]
- ANYWAY, I WAS HALFWAY DOWN
TO PANAMA, AND I SAW SOMETHING
IN THE LOCAL PAPER.
[narrator]
WHAT HE SAW WAS A STORY...
ABOUT HIS WIFE
GIVING MOUTH-TO-MOUTH
TO A HOMELESS MAN.
BUT HE KNEW THE TRUTH:
SHE WAS KISSING HIS BROTHER.
- WELL, I UNDERSTAND
WHAT THAT FEELS LIKE.
I WAS DUMPED TODAY.
I CAN'T TELL DAD HOW UPSET I AM
ABOUT IT BECAUSE HE'LL THINK
I SHOULD JUST BE
UPSET ABOUT YOU.
- HE WOULDN'T BE WRONG.
- [mutters]
WHAT?
- SEEMS LIKE WE'RE
GOING THROUGH THE SAME THING.
WHY DON'T WE
KEEP EACH OTHER'S SECRETS?
- YEAH, OKAY.
- LISTEN,
IF YOU PASS A MINI-MART,
POP-POP GETS A TREAT?
[narrator]
THE NEXT MORNING,
MICHAEL RAN INTO HIS SON
DOING SOMETHING SUSPICIOUS.
- MORNING!
- HI.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOIN'
WITH THAT FOOD?
- I WAS JUST GONNA EAT
SOME OF MY GRANDFATHER'S
FAVORITE FOODS IN MY ROOM.
IT'S THE FORM
THAT MY GRIEF IS TAKING.
- OKAY.
I THINK GEORGE MICHAEL'S
HIDING ANN IN THE ATTIC.
- [scoffs]
FROM WHO, THE NAZIS?
- NO, HIS GIRLFRIEND,
FROM ME.
I JUST CAUGHT HIM SNEAKING UP
TO HER IN THE ATTIC,
AND HE CLEARLY DID SO BECAUSE HE
THINKS I DON'T APPROVE.
I THINK I'M GONNA
INVITE HER TO THE WAKE.
WHY MAKE HIM HIDE?
WHY DO TO HIM WHAT--
- [sniffles]
- WHY DO TO HIM
WHAT DAD USED TO DO TO ME?
- [sobbing]
HE WAS SO AMAZING.
- THAT WAS ACTUALLY
AN EXAMPLE OF HOW NOT
SO AMAZING HE WAS.
YOU'RE REALLY GOING
THROUGH SOMETHING HERE, HUH?
- I KNOW!
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY--
ALL THOSE YEARS
WHEN I PRETENDED TO CRY,
I USED TO USE DAD'S DEATH
TO GET ME GOING.
I TRIED IT WITH MOM'S,
BUT I'D JUST END UP SMILING
AND RUINING IT.
BUT IT FEELS, LIKE, REAL.
YOU KNOW?
AND YOU HAVEN'T REALLY
ALLOWED YOURSELF TO GRIEVE
MUCH AT ALL, MICHAEL.
- MY RELATIONSHIP WITH DAD
WAS MUCH MORE--
MUCH MORE
COMPLICATED THAN YOURS.
IT WAS PREDICATED A LOT
ON SECRETS AND LIES.
THERE WASN'T
A LOT OF TRUST THERE.
- HERE HE COMES.
HERE COMES
JOHN WAYNE.
I'M NOT GONNA CRY
ABOUT MY PA.
I'M GONNA BUILD AN AIRPORT,
PUT MY NAME ON IT.
WHY, MICHAEL?
SO YOU CAN FLY AWAY
FROM YOUR FEELINGS?
YOU CAN KEEP 'EM BOTTLED UP,
BUT THEY WILL COME OUT, MICHAEL.
SOMETIMES
IN THE MOST UNEXPECTED--
HEY, WHERE THE [bleep]
ARE MY HARD-BOILED EGGS?
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, GOB
WAS PREPARING FOR THE ILLUSION
OF BEING BURIED ALIVE.
- BOY, YOU SURE GOT
THIS HOLE DUG OUT QUICK.
[narrator]
IN FACT, THE LABORER
HAD BEEN HIRED BY GEORGE SR.
THREE DAYS EARLIER...
FOR THE SAME HOLE.
AND BUSTER SEARCHED
FOR THE PERFECT CARD.
- "SOMEONE WANTED TO SEND YOU
A BIRTHDAY GREETING.
SEE YOU SOON!"
OH!
THAT IS WICKED.
[chuckles]
[narrator]
AND SOON, THE WAKE
THAT ICE HAD CATERED BEGAN.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IS THIS WHAT YOU'RE WEARING?
- MY FATHER'S DEAD, MAEBY.
- YEAH, BUT YOU'RE NOT,
AND ICE IS RIGHT THERE.
[narrator]
MAEBY KNEW THAT
IF SHE COULD GET HER MOTHER
TO HAVE AN AFFAIR,
SHE COULD EMANCIPATE.
- ALL POP-POP EVER WANTED
WAS TO SEE YOU WITH
ANOTHER MAN BESIDES DADDY.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA THROW ON A SKIRT,
TAKE OFF MY UNDERWEAR
AND MAKE YOUR POP-POP PROUD.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
LET ME ASK BARRY.
THAT MIGHT BE ENOUGH
RIGHT THERE.
- IS OSCAR
WEARING MY SUIT?
HEY--
YOU TELL MY BROTHER
YOU DON'T WEAR
A DEAD MAN'S PANTS.
SHAME ON HIM.
AND YOU SAY THAT TO HIM.
YOU SAY, "SHAME ON YOU."
- OKAY.
- SAY IT TO ME LIKE
YOU'RE GONNA SAY IT TO HIM.
- I'M PROBABLY NOT
GONNA SAY IT TO HIM.
- OKAY.
LOOK AT HER DOWN THERE.
DOES SHE LOOK SAD TO YOU?
- OH, MY GOD.
THAT'S ANN.
- WHO?
- IT'S THE GIRL
WHO RIPPED MY HEART OUT,
THE GIRL WHOSE FACE
WILL ALWAYS BE
ETCHED IN MY MIND.
- HER?
- SHE'S REALLY FUNNY.
- WELL, LET'S HOPE SO.
DON'T FORGET
THE CHICKEN WINGS!
- HEY! ANN!
YOU'RE HERE. THAT'S GREAT.
I WASN'T SURE
WHETHER YOU GOT MY MESSAGE.
- IT WASN'T A MESSAGE.
WE TALKED.
- UH, ANN?
DID DAD INVITE YOU?
- I FIGURED LIFE'S TOO SHORT.
YOU TWO SEEM TO
CARE FOR EACH OTHER.
WHY THROW THAT AWAY?
HUH?
OKAY.
- DO YOU THINK WE REALLY DO?
- A FATHER CAN TELL. OKAY?
IT'S AS ANN AS THE NOSE
ON PLAIN'S FACE.
[narrator]
AND BUSTER ARRIVED...
DRESSED IN THE MILITARY OUTFIT
GOB HAD PROCURED FOR HIM.
- WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU WEARING?
- IT'S ALL REGULATION,
MICHAEL.
TO GET THE TOP RIGHT,
THE PANTS HAD TO BE
A LITTLE SNUG.
IS THERE
A BIRTHDAY GIFT PILE?
HMM?
- A BIRTHDAY GIFT PILE?
[narrator]
MICHAEL RECALLED
WHAT BUSTER DID TO WHAT
HE THOUGHT WAS ROSA'S CAR...
WITH WHAT HE THOUGHT
WAS ROSA'S FAVORITE TOY.
- [driver]
HEY!
- YOURS IS THE FIRST.
- AND THE MOST WICKED.
[giggles]
- GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
WE CAN'T LET HIM KNOW
IT'S A WAKE.
- BUSTER!
LET'S GO GET THAT COFFIN
READY TO BE BURIED.
[both laughing]
[narrator]
AND SO THE FAMILY GATHERED
TO REMEMBER GEORGE SR.
- IF ANYONE WOULD LIKE
TO SAY ANYTHING ABOUT DAD,
NOW'S THE TIME.
ANYONE.
- ANYONE?
- PERHAPS MY SON GEORGE MICHAEL
WOULD LIKE TO SAY SOMETHING.
HUH? WANNA SHARE
YOUR FEELINGS? EH?
IT'S OKAY TO CRY, PAL.
IT'S OKAY.
- YEAH?
WOW.
HE'S REALLY GONE.
BUT I THINK THAT IF HE
WAS HERE RIGHT NOW,
I WOULD PROBABLY TELL HIM
THAT IT ALL WORKED OUT...
AND THAT, UM,
I'LL BE BRINGING YOU
SOME SALMON ROLLS RIGHT AWAY...
IN... HEAVEN.
- HOW MANY TIMES
I GOTTA TELL THIS KID
CHICKEN WINGS?
[narrator]
LINDSAY GOT UP TO SPEAK
IN AN OUTFIT
HER DAUGHTER HAD CHOSEN.
- MY FATHER
MEANT THE WORLD TO ME.
[sniffles]
- WIPE, MOM.
GIVE IT A WIPE.
- THAT'S A HOME RUN.
[narrator]
AND FINALLY,
MICHAEL GOT UP TO SPEAK.
- I HAD A VERY COMPLICATED
RELATIONSHIP WITH MY FATHER.
[blender whirring]
ICE, CAN WE--
CAN WE JUST COOL IT
ON THE SMOOTHIES FOR RIGHT NOW?
- THERE ARE SMOOTHIES?
- I COULD NEVER
TRUST MY FATHER.
BUT I ALWAYS WANT MY SON
TO BE ABLE TO TRUST ME,
SO FROM NOW ON,
WE'RE ALWAYS GONNA BE
HONEST WITH EACH OTHER.
OKAY?
'CAUSE THERE'S NOBODY I LOVE
MORE THAN YOU
IN THIS WHOLE WORLD.
- MICHAEL, LISTEN, CAN WE
MOVE THE EULOGY OUTSIDE,
SO I CAN TIME BEING
LOWERED INTO DAD'S GRAVE
WITH YOUR BIG FINISH?
- I'M DONE.
- WOW.
THAT WAS YOUR EULOGY?
GLAD DAD WASN'T AROUND
TO SEE THAT.
- THAT WAS GREAT.
- WELL, I MEANT IT.
SO NO MORE SECRET TRIPS
UP TO THE ATTIC. RIGHT?
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL DIDN'T WANT
TO BETRAY HIS GRANDFATHER,
BUT IT APPEARED HIS FATHER
ALREADY KNEW THE TRUTH.
- I HAVE POP-POP
IN THE ATTIC.
- WHAT?
THE MERE FACT THAT YOU CALL
MAKING LOVE "POP-POP"
TELLS ME YOU'RE NOT READY.
- HEY!
BEFORE WE LOSE THE SUN!
- COME ON.
- THE SPEECHES WE HEARD TODAY
ARE NOTHING MORE THAN WORDS.
BUT I WILL PROVE THAT I LOVE
MY FATHER MORE THAN ANYBODY.
[Europe's
The Final Countdown playing]
[whispers]
BUSTER!
[music continues]
[whispers]
STOP IT!
AS YOU CAN SEE,
THIS IS A NORMAL COFFIN.
TAKE ME HALFWAY AROUND.
- [grunting]
I WILL BECOME
MY DEAD FATHER'S BODY...
AS I AM LOWERED
INTO HIS GRAVE.
ALL RIGHT.
SPIN IT BACK AROUND.
- DEAD FATHER?
IS HE DE--
DAD'S DEAD?
- JUST KEEP IT TOGETHER, BUSTER,
AND SPIN THIS BACK AROUND.
- OH, MY GOD!
THE CARD! THE CARD!
[spectators gasping]
- [Gob]
SOMETHING'S GONE WRONG.
[murmuring, chattering]
- HOW ABOUT THAT?
[narrator]
MICHAEL NOTICED SOMETHING
IN THE DIRT.
- [sighs]
GLISTEN.
AND SUDDENLY HE REALIZED
WHAT HIS SON MEANT WHEN HE SAID
HE HAD POP-POP IN THE ATTIC.
- DAD?
DAD.
- HOW YOU DOIN', MICHAEL?
UH, HEY, BUT YOUR FATHER'S
ALIVE, MICHAEL.
HE'S ALIVE.
- HOW COULD YOU DO THIS TO US?
- I HAD NO CHOICE.
MY BROTHER IS WITH LUCILLE.
SHE'S DESTROYING THE FAMILY.
- YOU PUT THE ENTIRE BUSINESS IN
PERIL, YOU ESCAPE FROM PRISON,
THEN MAKE US THINK YOU'VE DIED?
- I-I-I'M AN INNOCENT MAN,
MICHAEL. I'M A PATSY.
I-I SIGNED SOME DOCUMENTS--
I THOUGHT THEY WERE
GONNA KILL ME.
DON'T TURN ME IN. OKAY?
CAN YOU HELP ME OUT?
[narrator]
AND FOR A MOMENT
MICHAEL WAS CONFLICTED.
- WELL, I'M NOT GONNA LET YOU
STAY HERE AND MAKE MY SON
AN ACCOMPLICE. OKAY?
I'M SORRY.
I'M NOT GONNA LET YOU
SPREAD YOUR GUILT TO HIM.
- ICE, MY MOTHER
HAS SOMETHING TO TELL YOU.
- I FIND YOU VERY ATTRACTIVE.
- SHE CLEANS UP NICE TOO.
TRUST ME.
- UH, I THINK I'M FINALLY
OFF THE CLOCK.
- I'M OUT OF HERE,
RIGHT?
- HI. DAD'S ALIVE.
HE'S HIDING IN THE ATTIC.
- HE'S UPSTAIRS?
- OH, MY GOD!
DAD?
- HE'S GONE.
STACK THE CHAFING DISHES
OUTSIDE BY THE MAILBOX.
I'M ON THE JOB.
- [scoffs]
I CAN'T SEEM TO GIVE THIS AWAY.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT!
AND I JUST FOUND THE WILL!
- CAN SOMEONE EXPLAIN TO ME
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- THANKS, MIKEY.
- YEAH. WELL,
NOW IT'S OUR SECRET.
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL MET UP WITH HIS SON,
THEIR ROLES NOW REVERSED.
- I'M SORRY.
FROM NOW ON WE'LL JUST TELL
THE TRUTH TO EACH OTHER.
- WE'RE GONNA TRY.
- YEAH.
- SO, WAIT, OBVIOUSLY
ANN WASN'T IN THE ATTIC.
SO YOU ACTUALLY DID
BREAK UP WITH HER?
- ACTUALLY,
SHE BROKE UP WITH ME.
THE GREAT THING IS, SHE WAS SO
MOVED BY WHAT YOU SAID TONIGHT
THAT WE'RE BACK TOGETHER.
- AH!
- [laughs]
YEAH!
- OH, IS THAT GREAT.
WELL, WE'RE FAMILY,
AND WE STICK TOGETHER, HUH?
HMM.
OKAY, LET'S GO
DIG UP YOUR UNCLE.
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT,
BUSTER FINDS OUT ABOUT
THE DEATH OF CAPTAIN KANGAROO.
MICHAEL GROWS WEARY
OF CARING FOR HIS FATHER.
- NO, POP-POP
DOES NOT GET A TREAT.
I JUST BROUGHT YOU A--
[bleep] PIZZA.
[narrator]
AND GOB FINALLY MAKES
THE COVER OF POOF MAGAZINE.