narrator:
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL WAS USING
THE BLUTH COMPANY CRANE
TO RETRIEVE THE FAMILY-OWNED
FROZEN BANANA STAND
AFTER IT HAD BEEN DUMPED
IN THE BAY,
A HOLIDAY TRADITION
AMONG THE LOCAL YOUTH.
SOON HE RETURNED HOME SO THAT
HE AND HIS SON--
- GEORGE MICHAEL?
narrator: COULD SHARE
THEIR HOLIDAY TRADITION
OF REBUILDING IT.
- ANOTHER ONE OF DAD'S SUITS?
- HEY, I'M THE PRESIDENT NOW.
FILLING DAD'S SHOES
LITERALLY,
EXCEPT HIS SHOES
DON'T FIT.
BUT I DID FINALLY GET
INTO DAD'S PANTS,
ALTHOUGH I HAD TO HAVE
THE CROTCH TAKEN IN A LITTLE.
- YOU KNOW, GOB, MAYBE
IT'S THE SUITS,
BUT I THINK YOU
MAY BE BEGINNING
TO ALIENATE SOME
OF THE EMPLOYEES DOWN AT WORK.
- WHAT? OH, THAT'S GREAT.
THE PRESIDENT HAS TO WORRY ABOUT
ALIENATING THE EMPLOYEES NOW.
narrator: IN FACT, GOB HAD
STARTED TO ALIENATE
SOME OF HIS COLLEAGUES.
THE WORST THAT COULD HAPPEN
IS I COULD SPILL SOME
ON MY $3,000 SUIT. COME ON!
- HEY!
- THE GUY IN THE $4,000 SUIT
IS HOLDING THE ELEVATOR
FOR THE GUY WHO DOESN'T MAKE
THAT IN THREE MONTHS.
COME ON!
WHY DON'T I JUST TAKE A WHIZ
THROUGH THIS $5,000 SUIT?
COME ON!
THEY LIKE ME JUST FINE.
YOU'LL SEE THAT TONIGHT
WHEN THEY TOAST ME
AT THE CHRISTMAS PARTY,
JUST LIKE THEY USED TO WITH DAD.
- THEY USED TO ROAST DAD
'CAUSE THEY THOUGHT THAT
HE HAD A SENSE OF HUMOR
ABOUT HIMSELF,
BUT HE DIDN'T,
AND NEITHER DO YOU.
- HEY, NOBODY LAUGHED LOUDER
THAN ME AT ANY JOKE ABOUT DAD.
YOU WERE THE ONE WHO'S ALL
MR. "I TAKE MYSELF TOO SERIOUSLY
ALL THE TIME."
narrator: MICHAEL DID TEND
TO TAKE THE CHRISTMAS PARTY
SOMEWHAT SERIOUSLY.
- MERRY CHRISTMAS.
YOU CAN GO AHEAD AND PUT THAT
RIGHT IN THE CHARITY BARREL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANKS A LOT.
SORRY, PAL. WE JUST CAN'T
HAVE THEM RESENT US.
- I KNOW SOME OF THE NUMBERS
HAVEN'T ALL ADDED UP,
AND THERE IS SOME SPECULATION.
THAT GEORGE HAS BEEN
INTO THE KITTY.
[laughter]
- "INTO THE KITTY!"
THAT'S AWESOME.
- FIRE TOM AND GET YOUR JACKASS
BROTHER OUT OF HERE.
- THIS YEAR
I'M NOT OFFICIALLY PRESIDENT,
AND IT'LL BE NICE
TO ACTUALLY HAVE SOME FUN
WITH MY SON
AT A CHRISTMAS PARTY.
- THANK GOD I DON'T HAVE TO GO.
- SO GLAD TO HEAR YOU SAY THAT.
I WANNA MEET SOMEONE THERE.
- WHAT?
SO I'M NOT INVITED TO THE
BLUTH COMPANY CHRISTMAS PARTY?
- OH, HONEY, OF COURSE
YOU CAN GO IF YOU WANT TO.
- THANKS, MOM.
- NO. YOU'RE NOT GOING TO THAT.
YOU SEE, IF I SHOW UP
WITH YOU,
IT'LL JUST MAKE ME
SEEM LIKE I'M A MOTHER.
- I'VE NEVER THOUGHT OF YOU
THAT WAY.
- THAT'S SWEET.
- WELL, I WON'T BE GOING.
I WILL BE HEAD TO TOE
IN BLUE MAKEUP UNTIL 8:01,
IN CASE THE BLUE MAN GROUP
NEEDS THEIR UNDERSTUDY, SO--
- NO, NO, YOU HAVE TO GO.
SO WHEN MEN FIND OUT
WE'RE IN AN OPEN RELATIONSHIP,
THEY'LL SEE YOU'RE NO THREAT.
PEOPLE HEAR THE NAME TOBIAS,
THEY THINK BIG, BLACK GUY.
- WELL, OBVIOUSLY
I'M NOT A BIG GUY.
I'M NOT A CARL WEATHERS,
PAR EXAMPLE.
- I FORGOT ABOUT CARL.
IS HE STILL SINGLE?
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL,
I NEED YOU TO HELP ME
FIX UP THE BANANA STAND.
- NO, I CAN'T.
I WAS SUPPOSED TO GO TO ANN'S
PARENTS' CHRISTMAS PARTY.
WE'RE MAKIN' YAMS.
- TONIGHT? TONIGHT
IS THE OFFICE PARTY.
- WELL, DID YOU WANT ME
TO GO TO THAT?
YOU'RE ALWAYS TELLING ME
NOT TO HAVE FUN AT THOSE THINGS.
- YES. WE MIGHT EVEN SNATCH A
GIFT FROM THE CHARITY BARREL.
- OH. OKAY, WELL--WELL, I THINK
ANN'S PARENTS
ARE HAVING
THEIR PARTY ON BETHLEHEM TIME,
WHICH IS PRETTY EARLY, SO MAYBE
I CAN MAKE AN APPEARANCE.
- MAKE AN APPEARANCE?
UH--UH--NO, NO. IT'S OKAY.
YOU BE WITH YAM.
IT'S FINE. IT'S GOOD.
- IT'S ANN.
- IT'S GOOD.
HAVE FUN.
- THE BOY'S PULLING AWAY
FROM YOU.
ARE WE HAVING YAMS?
- YEAH, I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
GOIN' ON WITH HIM.
YOU KNOW,
HE'S ON BETHLEHEM TIME.
HE'S SPENDING EVERY MOMENT
OF THE DAY WITH THIS GIRL.
IT'S, LIKE, I'M HIS FATHER.
HE SHOULD BE SPENDING MOST--
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
DON'T GET INVOLVED. BELIEVE ME.
WHEN I THOUGHT YOUR FIRST WIFE
WAS DRIVING US APART,
I DID NOT MAKE A STINK.
- YOU COMPLAINED ALL THE TIME,
AND SHE WAS MY ONLY WIFE.
AND SHE DIED.
- WELL, SEE, THINGS HAVE A WAY
OF WORKING THEMSELVES OUT.
[phone ringing]
- NONETHELESS, IT'S FAMILY FIRST
AT THE HOLIDAYS.
OH, GOD. IT'S MOM AGAIN.
- PUT IT ON SPEAKERPHONE.
I WANNA HEAR
HER BEAUTIFUL VOICE.
- [screams] MICHAEL!
THERE'S A HOLE IN THE WINDOW!
THERE'S BEEN A BREAK-IN!
GET OVER HERE!
- I'M LEAVING NOW.
- SOUNDS TENSE.
THAT MEANS SHE'S NOT GETTIN' ANY
FROM MY BROTHER, OSCAR.
- LOVELY. THAT'S NICE.
I HEARD ABOUT THE BANANA STAND,
AND NOW THERE'S BEEN A BREAK-IN.
BUT I HAVE A SURPRISE FOR
WHOEVER IT IS IF HE COMES BACK.
FIRST I BLOW HIM;
THEN I POKE HIM.
- GUY HAS NO IDEA
WHAT HE'S IN FOR.
YOU KNOW, MOM, ALL THE GLASS
SEEMS TO BE ON THE OUTSIDE.
PLUS, HERE'S YOUR LITTLE STATUE,
SO I GUESS WHAT THIS SAYS
TO ME IS,
I DOUBT ANYONE WAS
TRYING TO BREAK IN, MOM.
IF ANYTHING, SOMEONE
WAS TRYING TO BREAK OUT.
WHERE IS OSCAR?
- WELL, HE'S ON HIS WALKABOUT
OR PILGRIMAGE.
narrator: EVERY YEAR, OSCAR
ATTEMPTS THE 420-MILE WALK
FROM NEWPORT BEACH
TO BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA.
IN THE 12 YEARS
HE'S ATTEMPTED THIS,
HE'S NEVER
MADE IT PAST U.C. IRVINE.
- HE CALLS IT A QUEST
TO RECHARGE HIS CHI.
I CALL IT AN EXCUSE FOR HIM
TO SCORE HIS POT
AND WAG HIS PICKLE AT COEDS.
- YOU SOUND MAD, MOM, MAD ENOUGH
TO THROW ONE OF THESE
LITTLE LADY HEADS AT HIM.
- WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- WELL, MAYBE YOU'RE A LITTLE
BIT LONELY,
AND YOU'RE ACTING OUT
FOR ATTENTION.
- THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
I WANT YOU TO MOVE IN
WITH ME.
- WHAT? NO. NO. NO.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
DIDN'T YOU ADOPT A CHILD
FOR THIS VERY REASON?
SO THAT
YOU WOULD NEVER BE ALONE?
- MICHAEL, A MOTHER
DOESN'T HAVE A CHILD
TO GIVE HERSELF COMPANY.
ANNYONG WAS
TO TEACH BUSTER A LESSON.
- AND WHERE
IS THAT LITTLE LESSON?
- I SENT HIM TO THE MILFORD
ACADEMY TO TEACH HIM A LESSON.
I CAN'T REMEMBER ABOUT WHAT.
AND BUSTER LEFT THIS MORNING
TO FINISH HIS ARMY TRAINING.
narrator: IN FACT,
LUCILLE HAD REFUSED TO DRIVE HIM
TO THE ARMY BASE,
SO BUSTER WAS TAKING
HIS VERY FIRST BUS RIDE.
- I CAN'T CHANGE A HUNDRED.
- OH.
OH, GOD. OH.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN BUSTER
SAW SOMETHING INTERESTING.
- THAT COULD BE GOOD FOR ARMY.
[laughs]
[imitates whirring crane]
narrator: WHILE JUST
20 YARDS AWAY,
MICHAEL WENT TO WORK
REPAIRING THE BANANA STAND.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' HERE?
- MY MOM SIGNED ME
OUT OF SCHOOL EARLY
SO THEN SHE WOULDN'T HAVE
TO PICK ME UP LATER,
SO THEN SHE WOULDN'T BE LATE
FOR THE CHRISTMAS PARTY.
- THAT'S ABOUT THE WORST THING
I'VE EVER HEARD.
- I HAD TO DRIVE,
BECAUSE SHE HAD
A LITTLE BIT OF A BUZZ ON.
- NO. THAT'S IT.
- YOU DOING THIS ALONE?
- YEAH. WELL, THANKS.
I GUESS GEORGE MICHAEL'S
GETTIN' A LITTLE TOO OLD
TO HANG OUT WITH HIS DAD.
- YEAH, AND I'M GETTING TOO OLD
FOR MY MOM TO BE WITH ME.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
MAYBE WE SHOULD GO
TO THIS PARTY TOGETHER.
- REALLY?
- YEAH. YOU'RE MY LITTLE NIECE.
I THINK WE SHOULD BE SPENDING
A LITTLE BIT MORE TIME TOGETHER.
- YEAH, AND IF IT MAKES MY MOM
JEALOUS--
- AND GEORGE MICHAEL CAN RUN
BACK TO HIS PRECIOUS ANN.
GREAT. GOOD DEAL.
[bells jingling]
narrator: MICHAEL AND MAEBY
STOPPED BY THE OFFICE
TO SEE IF GOB NEEDED HELP
FOR THE PARTY
THAT WAS NOW HOURS AWAY.
- --KING $6,300 SUIT!
COME ON!
- HI THERE.
- WHAT'S SHE DOIN' HERE?
- MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU TOO,
UNCLE GOB.
- EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
- JUST DON'T WANT
PEOPLE'S KIDS GETTING
THEIR STICKY LITTLE FINGERS ALL
OVER THESE $2,600 PANTS.
- OH, YEAH, YOU THINK
THEY'RE GONNA GO
RIGHT FOR THE PANTS,
DO YOU?
- OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
SO, SHOULD--SHOULD--SHOULD--
SHOULD, SHOULD, SHOULD--
- SHH.
- SHOULD--SHOULD--SHOULD--
- WE'LL DO IT YOUR WAY.
I'M JUST HERE TO HAVE FUN.
- NOT TOO MUCH FUN, ALL RIGHT?
I ALREADY GAVE MY BIG
SEXUAL HARASSMENT SPEECH TODAY.
AND PLEASE REFRAIN
FROM DISCUSSING
OR ENGAGING IN ANY SORT OF
INTEROFFICE [bleep]
OR [bleep] OR FINGER [bleep]
OR [bleep] FISTING
OR [bleep]
OR EVEN [bleep].
EVEN THOUGH SO MANY PEOPLE IN
THIS OFFICE ARE BEGGING FOR IT.
AND IF ANYBODY DOES ANYTHING
WITH MY SISTER, LINDSAY,
I'LL TAKE OFF MY PANTS,
I'LL SHAVE [bleep]
AND I'LL PERSONALLY--
[bleep].
LET'S GET THIS GOING.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
NOW?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA LET THESE
PEOPLE GO HOME
AND CHANGE THEIR CLOTHES?
- I DON'T THINK WE NEED
PEOPLE TRYIN' TO COMPETE
WITH WHAT I'M WEARING.
EVERYBODY, COME OUT
OF YOUR OFFICES, PLEASE.
THE PARTY HAS NOW STARTED.
HERE WE GO.
LET'S GO.
[disco music]
EVERYBODY DANCE NOW.
- I THINK WE'RE OFF
TO A GREAT START.
narrator: AND SO, MICHAEL
STARTED TO BECOME RELAXED,
AND A SHORT TIME LATER,
HIS MOTHER ARRIVED
ANYTHING BUT.
- SOMEONE BROKE IN AGAIN.
THE LIQUOR IS GONE.
ALL OF IT--GONE.
narrator: IN FACT, GOB HAD
STOLEN IT EARLIER THAT DAY
TO CUT DOWN ON THE COST
OF THE PARTY.
- HEY, NEED A HAND WITH THAT?
- NO, AL. I WANNA SPILL BOOZE
ALL OVER MY F--
- I'M ALL ALONE THERE, MICHAEL.
- YOU KNOW, BUSTER'S ONLY
STATIONED ABOUT FIVE MILES AWAY.
narrator: IN FACT, BUSTER NEVER
WENT TO THE ARMY.
HE'D GOTTEN HOOKED PLAYING
THE SKILL CRANE
AND MISSED HIS FIRST DAY.
[trilling]
SOMEWHAT ASHAMED
AND WITH NOWHERE TO GO,
- HEY, BUSTER.
narrator: HE RETURNED HOME.
[door closes]
- [gasps]
BUSTER!
THANK GOD YOU'RE BACK!
THERE'S NO SHAME
IN BEING A COWARD.
- COWARD?
I'M NOT A COWARD.
WOULD A COWARD HAVE THIS?
- WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
- THESE ARE MY AWARDS, MOTHER,
FROM ARMY.
THE SEAL
IS FOR MARKSMANSHIP,
AND THE GORILLA
IS FOR SAND RACING.
- YOU'RE DOING WELL?
- I WAS JUST
DROPPING THESE OFF.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
THEY'RE PUTTING ME IN SOMETHING
CALLED HERO SQUAD.
- YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE ABANDONED BY YOUR SON.
- DO YOU SEE MY SON?
HE CHOSE HIS GIRLFRIEND
OVER ME.
- HOW THE WORM HAS TURNED.
LOOK WHO FEELS THE STING
OF AN UNGRATEFUL CHILD.
- MOTHER, YOU HAVE TO RECEIVE
SOMETHING TO BE UNGRATEFUL.
THE POINT IS, I'M NOT GETTIN'
WORKED UP OVER IT TONIGHT.
I'M NOT GONNA
LET ANYTHING BOTHER ME.
- GOOD. I'LL GET A DRINK
AND THEN GO HOME AND WAIT
FOR YOU TO COME STAY WITH ME.
THANK GOD
THEY'VE GOT MY BRANDS HERE.
narrator: THIS WAS
AN UNACCEPTABLE SOLUTION.
- HEY, TOBIAS, IT'S MICHAEL.
I HOPE YOU GET THIS.
I NEED YOU TO
GO OVER TO MY MOTHER'S TONIGHT.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
TOBIAS MISSED THE CALL
FROM THE BLUTH COMPANY
AND IT WENT THROUGH
TO MICHAEL'S HOME VOICE MAIL.
- THE BLUE MEN!
[phone beeps]
- YOU HAVE 101 UNHEARD MESSAGES.
FIRST MESSAGE.
- MICHAEL, IT'S YOUR MOTHER--
[beep]
MICHAEL, PICK UP.
[beep] HAPPY THANKSGIVING--
MICHAEL, IT'S MOTHER--
MICHAEL, PICK UP--
[beep]
- HEY, TOBIAS, IT'S MICHAEL.
- [groans]
BLUTH COMPANY.
narrator: AND LINDSAY SHOWED UP
AT THE CHRISTMAS PARTY.
UNFORTUNATELY, SHE DIDN'T
REALIZE
THAT THE EMPLOYEES HAD BEEN
THREATENED AGAINST FLIRTING.
- OH, HELLO, TED.
OH, IF YOU'RE WORRIED
ABOUT MY HUSBAND, IT'S FINE.
HE'S NO BIGGER THAN A CUB SCOUT.
YOU COULD TAKE HIM,
AND YOU COULD CERTAINLY TAKE ME.
- THIS HAS BEEN PLEASANT
AND PROFESSIONAL.
GOOD LUCK
IN THE COMING BUSINESS YEAR.
[chuckles] HEY, YOU GUYS ARE
STICKING STUFF ON GOB'S SUIT?
- SHH.
GO AWAY.
YOU'RE GONNA RUIN IT.
- AUNT LINDSAY,
HOW'S THE PARTY?
- IT IS THE WORST
CHRISTMAS PARTY
I'VE EVER BEEN TO IN MY LIFE.
YEAH. WATCH THIS.
[sucks teeth]
YEP. LIKE MY LAST 10 YEARS.
AND MY DAUGHTER WON'T
GIVE ME THE TIME OF DAY.
HOW WAS YOUR PARTY?
- OH, IT WAS GOOD.
THEY'RE KIND OF RELIGIOUS,
ANN'S FAMILY, SO IT WAS--
YEAH, IT WAS JUST KIND OF--
narrator: THE WORD GEORGE
MICHAEL WAS SEARCHING FOR
WAS "CREEPY".
[piano]
[Ann singing out of tune]
- GIVE YOU A HAND
WITH THAT, LITTLE FELLA.
- [singing out of tune]
- HEY, I WAS TALKIN'
TO THE SOUND GUY,
AND HE SAID
HE'S GOT THIS KARAOKE THING.
- YEAH. LET'S DO IT. PUT
THE FIRST SONG ON IN THE BOOK.
- OKAY.
- OKAY? THANKS VERY MUCH.
HEY. I THOUGHT YOU WERE
AT YOUR PARTY.
- NO, NO.
THEY SAID I COULD LEAVE
FOR THE SECOND HOUR
OF SILENT PRAYER.
BUT ANN AND I DO HAVE
TO GO BACK, SO I SHOULD--
I SHOULD GO SOON.
- UNCLE MICHAEL--
- OKAY. I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
SORRY. I GOTTA GO DO THIS.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
SANG A DUET WITH HIS NIECE.
- [singing] GONNA HOLD HER TIGHT
GONNA GRAB SOME
AFTERNOON DELIGHT
- MY DAUGHTER DOESN'T NEED ME.
- NEITHER DOES MY DAD.
narrator: HAD GEORGE MICHAEL
AND LINDSAY STAYED,
THEY MIGHT HAVE DISCOVERED
WHAT MICHAEL AND MAEBY DID--
THAT "AFTERNOON DELIGHT"
WAS MORE ADULT-THEMED
THAN ITS INNOCENT MELODY
WOULD HAVE YOU BELIEVE.
- [singing]
AND THE THOUGHT OF RUBBING YOU
IS GETTING SO EXCITING
- [singing]
SKYROCKETS IN FLIGHT
- HANG ON, MAEBY.
- [singing]
AFTERNOON DELIGHT
- LISTEN.
I'M GONNA GO GET SOME MORE
PUNCH, BECAUSE IT IS TOAST TIME.
OKAY? NO, NO, NO.
IT'LL LOOK WORSE.
GO THAT WAY.
- SO LET'S TOAST ME.
WHO'S FIRST?
TOM, WHY DON'T YOU
COME UP HERE AND TALK ABOUT ME
FOR A FEW MINUTES?
- UH, I WANNA THANK THE BLUTH
FAMILY FOR HIRING ME BACK.
IT'S BEEN A TOUGH
COUPLE YEARS.
- MY BROTHER DID THAT.
TALK ABOUT ME.
- OH, OKAY.
UH, YOU CERTAINLY
DO LOVE THOSE SUITS.
- AT SEVEN GRAND, YOU'D BETTER
BELIEVE I LOVE 'EM.
I MEAN,
LOOK AT WHAT YOU'RE WEARING.
YOU LOOK LIKE CRAP.
I MEAN, AT LEAST THIS IS--
[grunts]
WHO DID THIS?
[all snickering]
YOU DO THIS, TOM?
- NO.
- YOU'RE A REAL SMART-ASS.
YOU KNOW THAT, TOM?
- LOOK, I DON'T KNOW HIM
VERY WELL,
BUT GOB SEEMS LIKE
HE'D BE A REALLY SMART BOSS.
[laughter]
PLEASE DON'T LAUGH.
LOOK, HE'S A GREAT MAGICIAN.
[hysterical laughter]
- THAT'S EVEN BETTER!
- [bleep] YOU, TOM.
- PLEASE DON'T.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE FIRED.
- NO. YOU'RE ALL FIRED,
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF YOU.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
- I DIDN'T KNOW THE LYRICS.
WHERE'S EVERYBODY GOIN'?
- WE DON'T WORK HERE ANYMORE.
- WHAT?
- IS YOUR SISTER STILL AROUND?
narrator: THE CHRISTMAS PARTY
HAD BEEN A DISASTER.
- I DID THE RIGHT THING,
MICHAEL.
IF I DON'T FIRE THEM, HOW DO I
TEACH A LESSON TO THE OTHERS?
- THERE ARE NO OTHERS.
YOU FIRED EVERYONE.
- OH, THAT--THAT'S GREAT.
THE GUY WHO'S DIRTY DANCING
WITH HIS NIECE
IS GONNA TELL THE GUY
IN THE $3,600 SUIT
HOW TO RUN THE BUSINESS.
COME ON.
- I KNOW.
MAYBE WE'RE BETTER OFF
WITH ME BEING BUSINESSLIKE
AND YOU BEING THE GOOD-TIME,
USELESS PARTY GUY.
- IT GOT US THIS FAR.
- MM-HMM.
- AND I MUST SAY THAT
I MISS THE LAUGHTER.
OH, GOD,
HOW THEY USED TO LAUGH WITH ME.
- AT YOU. WE GOTTA FIGURE OUT A
WAY TO HIRE EVERYBODY BACK.
A MEETING.
- A PARTY.
- NO. WE JUST HAD A PARTY.
- YEAH, BUT I DIDN'T GET
TO HAVE ANY FUN.
narrator: SO MICHAEL WENT TO
WORK ON ANOTHER CHRISTMAS PARTY,
THIS TIME WITH THE HELP
OF HIS NIECE.
- I REALLY APPRECIATE
YOU DOING THIS.
I DIDN'T WANNA
ASK GEORGE MICHAEL.
I MEAN, DID YOU SEE THAT HE
SHOWED UP AT THE PARTY
FOR FIVE MINUTES AND LEFT
WITHOUT EVEN SAYING GOOD-BYE?
- HEY, MY MOM DOESN'T EVEN WANNA
BE IN THE SAME ROOM WITH ME.
- MICHAEL, I WAS ALMOST ATTACKED
LAST NIGHT IN MY OWN HOME.
I WALK IN, AND THERE'S A COLORED
MAN IN MY KITCHEN.
- "COLORED"?
WHAT COLOR WAS HE EXACTLY?
- BLUE.
- HELLO, LUCILLE.
[horn blares]
- I SENT HIM TO YOUR HOUSE
TO KEEP YOU SAFE.
- WELL, HE DID A TERRIBLE JOB.
DIDN'T HE?
I NEED SOMEONE ELSE,
SOMEONE BETTER.
WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE?
SHE'S GOT THICK ARMS.
- MOM, YOU JUST NEED
TO CALM DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
YOU'RE SO TENSE.
- HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO CALM DOWN?
- SOUNDS TENSE.
THAT MEANS SHE'S NOT GETTIN' ANY
FROM MY BROTHER OSCAR.
- I MEAN, MAYBE I SHOULD
MOVE IN WITH YOU.
narrator: AND MICHAEL REALIZED
HE NEEDED TO RETRIEVE
HIS UNCLE OSCAR.
- HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO GO ON A ROAD TRIP?
- NO. I WANNA STAY HERE
WITH HER. LET'S GO.
narrator: AND SO THE TWO OF THEM
PREPARED TO DRIVE UP THE COAST.
- OKAY, YOU'RE IN CHARGE
OF THE RADIO,
AND WE'RE NOT STOPPING
UNTIL WE FIND UNCLE OSCAR.
- THERE HE IS.
- MY MOM IS VERY STRESSED OUT,
AND SHE NEEDS SOMETHING
THAT I CAN'T GIVE HER--
UM, MAYBE A LITTLE
AFTERNOON DELIGHT.
narrator: OSCAR THOUGHT THAT
MICHAEL WAS REFERRING TO
A PARTICULAR BRAND OF CANNABIS
NAMED AFTERNOON DEELITE,
A STRAIN FAMOUS FOR
SLOWING BEHAVIOR.
- WELL, SURE.
THE QUESTION IS,
WHICH WAY DO I TRY
TO GET IT IN HER?
- I DON'T NEED ANY DETAILS.
- MAYBE I'LL PUT IT
IN HER BROWNIE.
- HEY!
- WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
- WHAT?
[loudly] OH, OH. MY EARS.
THE DOCTOR SAID I CAN'T
GO TO SLEEP FOR FIVE HOURS,
OR I MIGHT DIE
OR SOMETHING.
OH, I GOT BLOWN,
SO I CAN'T SLEEP.
- HEY, HAVE YOU SEEN MAEBY?
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA BELIEVE THIS.
APPARENTLY MY DAD AND MAEBY
TOOK A DRIVE UP THE COAST.
- YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
- UH-OH. I SHOULD
NOT HAVE PICKED AT THAT.
THAT'S BLOOD.
- THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
SO SHE'S GOT A NEW PARENT.
- YEAH. NOW MY DAD'S
GOT A NEW KID.
- I'M GONNA LIE DOWN
FOR A LITTLE BIT, BUT JUST--
I C--I CAN'T FALL--
- HEY, HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO
COME TO THE PARTY WITH ME TODAY?
narrator: AND OSCAR
WAS GIVING LUCILLE
A LITTLE AFTERNOON DEELITE.
- THESE ARE REALLY DELICIOUS.
- I'LL GET SOME MORE.
- [singing] OKAY
MM-HMM
- WHERE DID SHE GO?
narrator: AND SOON, THE SECOND
BLUTH COMPANY CHRISTMAS PARTY
IN AS MANY DAYS BEGAN.
- YOU ARE NOT FIRED, SIR.
- I REALLY APPRECIATE THAT.
- YOU GOT IT.
HERE YOU GO. MERRY CHRISTMAS.
WHERE THE HELL IS MY BROTHER?
- SURE, THE GUY
IN THE $600 BANANA SUIT.
COME ON!
- HI.
[suit squeaking]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
- HEY, DON'T BE MAD AT ME 'CAUSE
YOU DIDN'T THINK ABOUT
GETTING UP AT 6:00 A.M.
AND GOING OUT TO TARZANA
TO GET THE OLD BANANA SUIT
OUT OF STORAGE.
BUT IT'S WORTH IT,
BECAUSE IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO MAKE PEOPLE LAUGH AGAIN.
WITH ME.
AND WHAT'S FUNNIER THAN A GUY
IN--OH--HEY, WAIT. HEY.
[laughing,
Gob continues shouting]
OKAY.
[laughter]
narrator: LATER, GOB WAS
INSIDE THE BANANA STAND,
AND IT WAS GETTING PRETTY HOT
IN THERE,
SO HE DECIDED
TO LOSE A LAYER.
- HEY, LOOK. THERE'S YOUR MOM
AND GEORGE MICHAEL.
I GUESS THEY DID
COME TO SUPPORT US AFTER ALL.
- LOOK AT THAT.
THEY'RE ALL OVER EACH OTHER
WITH THEIR LITTLE SECRETS.
- WHAT CAN YOU DO, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
HOW WOULD YOU FEEL
ABOUT SINGING A LITTLE KARAOKE?
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
LINDSAY WASN'T THERE TO SEE ALL
OF MICHAEL AND MAEBY'S SONG
AND WAS ABOUT
TO HAVE A SIMILAR REVELATION.
- [singing] COULD NOT BE CAUGHT
THAT DIDN'T BITE
BUT YOU GOT SOME BAIT
A-WAITIN', AND I THINK I MIGHT
TRY NIBBLING
A LITTLE AFTERNOON DELIGHT
- THAT'S MY WIFE AND NEPHEW.
- [singing] SKYROCKETS IN FLIGHT
- WE HAVE
AN OPEN RELATIONSHIP.
narrator: JUST THEN, LUCILLE
ARRIVED CRAVING A FROZEN BANANA.
AND THE EFFECTS OF LINDSAY
AND GEORGE MICHAEL'S
"AFTERNOON DELIGHT"
WAS OVERSHADOWED--
- MOM?
narrator: BY THE EFFECTS
OF OSCAR AND LUCILLE'S
AFTERNOON DEELITE.
- TOBIAS--TOBIAS, WATCH OUT.
narrator: TOBIAS COULDN'T HEAR--
- TOBIAS!
narrator: AND DIDN'T MANAGE TO
GET OUT OF THE WAY IN TIME.
- WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
[thud]
narrator:
AND GOB COULDN'T MOVE FREELY.
LUCILLE TRIED
TO COME TO A STOP,
BUT THE CAR
HIT GOB'S BANANA PEEL.
[goofy laughter]
[wood crashing]
- I CAN'T GET OUT OF HERE.
I'M STUCK.
- MOM, ARE YOU CRAZY? YOU
COULD'VE KILLED SOMEBODY.
- HEY, MIKEY, RELAX.
IT'S JUST A GIANT BANANA.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN BUSTER
SAW AN OPPORTUNITY TO BE A HERO.
- GOB?
- MOM, I'M STUCK!
- I GOT YOU, BROTHER!
[engine revving]
[giddy laughter]
[laughter]
narrator: AND FOR THE SECOND
TIME SINCE HE BECAME PRESIDENT,
GOB HEARD THE SWEET SOUND
OF LAUGHTER.
- THEY'RE LAUGHING WITH ME,
MICHAEL.
THEY'RE LAUGHING WITH ME!
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
BUSTER'S NEWFOUND SKILLS
DID NOT INVOLVE
LOWERING GENTLY.
- OOH. OH.
- HEY, IT'S TOBIAS.
WHO WANTS TO TAKE ME
TO THE HOSPITAL?
narrator:
AND SO FATHER AND SON REUNITE,
REBUILDING THE BANANA STAND
FOR A SECOND TIME.
- HEY. CAN I GIVE YOU A HAND?
- HEY. YEAH.
THAT'D BE GREAT.
- OKAY.
OH, I'M SORRY ABOUT--
IT'S EMBARRASSING, THE WHOLE--
- LISTEN, I, UH--
I'VE BEEN A LITTLE OUT OF LINE
LATELY.
YOU'RE ENTITLED
TO BE WITH YOUR GIRLFRIEND,
AND I GUESS I GOT
A LITTLE BIT JEALOUS.
- YEAH. WELL, ME TOO.
- YEAH.
- OKAY.
[Michael whistling
"Afternoon Delight"]
- [both singing]
GONNA GRAB SOME AFTERNOON--
- IT DOES NOT SEEM LIKE
IT WOULD BE THAT DIRTY.
- IT'S--IT IS CATCHY.
RIGHT. THAT'S THE THING.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
THE BLUE MAN GROUP
FINALLY CALLS FOR TOBIAS
WITH A LIFE-CHANGING
OPPORTUNITY.
UNFORTUNATELY, HE CAN'T HEAR IT,
AND HIS LIFE STAYS THE SAME.