male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH HAD SCHEDULED
A MEETING WITH STAN SITWELL,
THE BLUTH COMPANY'S
CHIEF COMPETITOR.
- WHY ARE WE HAVING THIS MEETING
AT HOME?
- WELL, LET HIM SEE
HE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE
WHO BUILDS SOLID HOUSES,
YOU KNOW?
I THINK HE'LL BE
PRETTY IMPRESSED,
KNOCK ON WOOD.
[knocking]
narrator: IN FACT,
MICHAEL WAS MEETING AT HOME
AT THE BEHEST
OF HIS FUGITIVE FATHER.
- KNOCK ON WOOD.
[knocking]
- DON'T YOU FIND
THE TIMING OF THIS MEETING
A LITTLE SUSPICIOUS?
RIGHT BEFORE WE PLAY
HIS COMPANY IN SOFTBALL?
- NO, NO,
OUR BUSINESS IS IN TROUBLE,
AND I THINK
HE SEES AN OPPORTUNITY.
SO, I FIGURED THE GUY'S
A FAMILY MAN,
WHY NOT INVITE HIM OVER,
- LET HIM SEE US IN OUR ELEMENT.
- I HOPE YOU DON'T MEAN
THE WHOLE FAMILY...
'CAUSE GEORGE MICHAEL'S
OFF WITH ANN.
- ANN?
HMM. THAT'LL PLAY WELL
WITH SITWELL.
"WHERE'S YOUR SON?"
"HE'S OUT WITH ANN."
"WHO'S ANN?"
"DON'T ASK ME,
I'M JUST THE BOY'S FATHER."
- HEY, SCREW SITWELL!
HE COMES IN HERE TELLING US
HOW TO BUILD OUR HOUSES,
HOW TO RAISE OUR KIDS.
NO, WE KNOW WHAT WE'RE DOING.
WE DON'T NEED
ANY HELP FROM HIM.
DAMN IT.
THIS THING GOT PUSHED IN AGAIN.
GONNA NEED A BUTTER KNIFE.
- THIS IS WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
GEORGE MICHAEL'S GOT THESE
POWERFUL LITTLE FINGERS.
HE SHOULD BE HERE.
- HEY, HOW DO YOU THINK I FEEL?
HE'S THE ONE WHO SAID HE WOULD
HELP ME ON THIS ESSAY
FOR "THE OLD MAN AND THE SEA."
- I'LL HELP YOU WITH THAT LATER.
- OH, GREAT.
OKAY.
SO YOU HAVE TO READ THIS,
AND THEN EXPLAIN IT,
AND, THIS IS IMPORTANT,
YOU HAVE TO SAY IT
IN MY OWN WORDS, OKAY?
SMART, BUT NOT TOO SMART.
LET'S HAVE A FOUR-SYLLABLE MAX.
- DO YOU WANNA SAY SOMETHING
OR SHOULD I, TOBIAS?
- NO, I BELIEVE IN
LETTING CHILDREN
LEARN FROM THEIR MISTAKES,
MICHAEL.
THEY MAKE A MISTAKE ONCE,
THEY SHAN'T MAKE IT TWICE.
OH, HERE I GO!
DON'T WORRY, IT HAS
NOT FALLEN INTO THE GARAGE.
KNOCK ON WOOD.
[loud crash]
- YOU GONNA WANT TO
HELP ME WITH THAT?
- NO, I CAN'T.
I HAVE AN AUDITION TOMORROW.
I'M UP FOR A MINOR, BUT MEATY,
ROLE IN A FEATURE FILM.
- "CONFIDENCE MAN TWO."
- OH, YEAH?
I DIDN'T SEE
THE FIRST CONFIDENCE MAN.
- NO, CONFIDENCE MAN TWO
IS MY CHARACTER.
I THINK I'LL DRIVE UP TODAY
AND PLOT MY ROUTE TO THE STUDIO.
- HOW 'BOUT I COME WITH YOU?
I MEAN, I COULD
HELP YOU PREPARE.
- YES, WELL,
IT'S FOR A CON MAN,
WHICH I DON'T THINK
YOU KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT.
AND BESIDES,
DON'T YOU HAVE SCHOOL?
- NO, UM...
TODAY IS "HELP YOUR DAD
FOLLOW HIS DREAM" DAY.
- GREAT.
WE CAN TAKE THE CARPOOL LANE.
- I NEED ICE.
- I'M GLAD SITWELL'S
COMING OVER.
LET HIM SEE THAT
WE'RE DOING FINE AS A FAMILY.
THE ONLY HELP WE NEED
IS FROM EACH OTHER.
- AND APPARENTLY WHATEVER'S
IN THAT BOTTLE.
- THANKS FOR REMINDING ME.
MY TEAMOCIL.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
TEAMOCIL?
ISN'T THAT THAT SUPPLEMENT
THAT YOU AND TOBIAS WERE HOCKING
BEFORE THE F.D.A. SHUT YOU DOWN?
narrator: IN THE MID '90s,
TOBIAS FORMED A FOLK BAND
TO PROMOTE A SUPPLEMENT
THAT PROMISED BETTER UNITY
AND TEAMWORK.
- [singing] TEAMOCIL
- TEAMOCIL MAY DECREASE
YOUR SEX DRIVE.
- [singing] TEAMOCIL
- GOOD JOB, BUDDY.
- THANKS, FRIEND.
SINCE I'VE BEEN
TAKING THIS AGAIN,
I'VE BEEN GETTING ALONG
GREAT WITH MY HUSBAND.
YOU'RE TAKING IT FOR
THE SIDE EFFECT, AREN'T YOU?
- MICHAEL!
- OH, GOD.
MOTHER, NOT A GOOD TIME.
I'M HAVING A MEETING HERE.
- LOOK AT WHAT BUSTER
SENT FROM THE ARMY.
- IT'S BLACKED OUT.
- OH, THE GOVERNMENT.
KEEP READING.
- "SERGEANT BLANK
IS TREATING ME VERY BLANK,
"AND IT LOOKS LIKE
I'LL BE SHIPPING OFF TO BLANK
"IN ABOUT A BLANK.
I BLANK YOU, MOTHER.
BUSTER."
- I'VE DONE EVERYTHING I CAN.
I EVEN TRIED TO CONVINCE THEM
HE'S GAY,
BUT NO ONE WOULD BELIEVE
THAT A WOMAN LIKE ME
WOULD HAVE A GAY SON.
- WELL, YOU CERTAINLY TRIED.
YOU GUYS WORE MATCHING OUTFITS
TILL HE WAS 12.
narrator:
EVEN ONCE ON A MAGAZINE COVER
THAT HAD BEEN MOCKED
WITHIN THE FAMILY FOR YEARS.
LUCILLE, I-I'LL SAY IT AGAIN.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN IN THE ARMY.
REMEMBER, LUCILLE?
- NO, I DON'T.
- GET ME A VODKA, ROCKS.
- MOM, IT'S BREAKFAST.
- AND A PIECE OF TOAST.
- PLEASE, STAN SITWELL'S
COMING OVER.
- THAT HAIRLESS FREAK
IS COMING HERE?
NONE OF HIS HAIR IS REAL,
YOU KNOW.
- YOU MEAN THE GUY
WE'RE MEETING WITH
CAN'T EVEN GROW HIS OWN HAIR?
COME ON!
- IT'S CALLED ALOPECIA,
AND I'D APPRECIATE IT
IF WE COULD ALL BE
SENSITIVE TO IT, OKAY?
HE HAPPENS TO BE A VERY MODEST
AND GENEROUS MAN.
- MODEST AND GENEROUS?
- THEN WHY IS HE ALWAYS WAVING
GIANT $10 MILLION CHECKS
OVER HIS HEAD
EVERY TIME SOME--
- GO AHEAD, MOM.
FINISH YOUR THOUGHT.
"EVERY TIME SOME CHILDREN'S
HOSPITAL NEEDS FUNDING"?
- NONETHELESS, WE COULD GET
A GIANT CHECKBOOK TOO.
WE'RE JUST NOT
THAT STARVED FOR ATTENTION.
narrator: AND LATER,
SITWELL LAID OUT HIS PLANS.
- SORRY THAT MY SON
COULDN'T BE HERE.
- LET ME GUESS.
GIRLFRIEND.
YOU KNOW, IT COULD BE WORSE.
HE COULD WANNA MARRY
YOUR MOTHER.
[laughs]
OH, I'M SORRY, IS YOUR FAMILY
NOT LAUGHING AT THAT YET?
OKAY, LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT I'M OFFERING.
YOU GOT A WONDERFUL
PIECE OF PROPERTY HERE
THAT'S GOING NOWHERE.
SO WHAT I PROPOSE
IS A CO-VENTURE
WITH YOUR SUDDEN VALLEY
DEVELOPMENT.
THE FIRST THING YOU MIGHT WANNA
CHANGE, THOUGH, IS THE NAME.
YOU KNOW, SUDDEN VALLEY CONJURES
UP THE IMAGE OF A SINKHOLE, NO?
- I TOLD THAT TO DAD.
I TOLD THAT TO MY DAD.
- I'M THINKING
"PARADISE GARDENS."
- [wind whistling]
- I SWEAR TO GOD
I HAVE THAT WRITTEN--
I WANT YOU TO SEE THAT
SO YOU DON'T THINK THAT I'M--
I HAVE THAT WRITTEN DOWN
ON MY NOTEBOOK.
narrator:
WHEN GEORGE SR. WAS IN CHARGE,
HE HAD A HABIT OF SHOOTING DOWN
ANY IDEA MICHAEL CAME UP WITH.
- AND SUDDEN VALLEY
JUST SORT OF IMPLIES
THAT SOMETHING AWFUL
COULD HAPPEN ALL OF A SUDDEN.
YOU KNOW, PLUS, IT'S ON A HILL.
- WHAT, ARE YOU TAKING,
STUPID PILLS?
COME ON.
SAVE US SOME MONEY.
narrator: THIS WAS
A MANAGEMENT TOOL
THAT HE USED TO KEEP MICHAEL
WORKING FOR HIS APPROVAL.
- THAT WAS A HARD ONE
TO SAY NO TO.
- THE ONLY THING I ASK IS,
OUT OF THE 450 HOMES WE BUILD,
ONE BE GIVEN TO A DISADVANTAGED
FAMILY FROM THE INNER CITY.
- THAT'S GREAT.
SO THE OTHER 449 FAMILIES
LIVE IN FEAR?
IS THAT WHAT WE'RE SAYING?
I MEAN, COME ON!
WHERE'S YOUR DECEN--
WHAT THE HELL
JUST FELL OFF YOUR FACE?
ONE OF THIS GUY'S EYEBROWS JUST
FELL IN THE BOWL CANDY BEANS.
- I ALWAYS CARRY A SPARE.
- WELL, I HOPE YOU ALSO CARRY
A SPARE BOWL OF CANDY BEANS.
- GOB!
I'M VERY IMPRESSED
WITH THE OFFER,
AND I'M GONNA RUN IT UPSTAIRS,
SEE WHAT KIND OF REACTION
IT GETS.
- HMM?
- SO TO SPEAK.
narrator: MICHAEL HOPED
TO IMPRESS HIS FATHER.
- I THINK IT ALL SOUNDS
PRETTY GOOD.
PRETTY GOOD?
IT WAS HORRIBLE.
WHAT, ARE YOU TAKING,
STUPID PILLS AGAIN?
narrator: BUT THEIR OLD DYNAMIC
RETURNED WHEN GEORGE SR. DID.
GOB WAS THE ONLY ONE DOWN THERE
WHO KNEW HOW TO HANDLE
THAT HAIRLESS FREAK.
- THANK GOD WE HAVE GOB
ON OUR TEAM.
- YOU KNOW, DAD, GOB DOESN'T
REALLY DO ALL THAT MUCH
FOR OUR TEAM.
IN FACT, I THINK IT'S TIME
THAT I GET PUT BACK IN CHARGE.
- MICHAEL, LISTEN TO ME.
LATELY, YOUR IDEAS,
THEY'RE HORRIBLE,
AND SITWELL'S JUST TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT OUR BATTING ORDER
FOR THE SOFTBALL GAME
ON SATURDAY,
I'M TELLING YOU.
- GOB SAID THE SAME THING, DAD,
BUT I-I DOUBT THAT THIS GUY'S
TRYING TO DROP $15 MILLION
TO FIND OUT OUR BATTING ORDER.
- HEY, THIS GAME
GOES WAY, WAY BACK.
narrator:
IT WAS A FIERCE RIVALRY,
WITH GEORGE SR. USING EVERYTHING
AT HIS DISPOSAL TO WIN.
- NO HAIR.
HEY, WE GOT NO HAIR.
narrator: WHILE STAN SITWELL
USED THE GAME
TO RAISE FUNDS FOR
UNDERPRIVILEGED CHILDREN.
- OH, I THINK
ONE OF YOUR ORPHANS
IS HEADING TOWARDS THE STREET.
STRIKE THREE.
YOU GO DOWN THERE,
AND YOU TELL HIM
TO GO SCREW HIMSELF
AND YOU APOLOGIZE
TO YOUR BROTHER.
WE NEED HIM ON OUR SIDE,
AND WE NEED HIM HAPPY.
- WHERE'S SITWELL?
- SORRY, I TOLD HIM
TO SCREW OFF.
BUT GET THIS,
HE OFFERED ME A JOB.
- WHAT?
- WELL, I'M NOT WAITING
ON MY BROTHER.
I PASS.
YOU LOOK SURPRISED.
- I'M SORRY.
I MUST'VE PUT IT ON TOO HIGH.
BUT YOU WERE RIGHT.
IT WAS A BAD OFFER, AND YOU WERE
SMART ENOUGH NOT TO TAKE IT.
YOU GOT GUMPTION.
YOU SPEAK YOUR MIND.
THAT MEANS YOU'RE GOOD ENOUGH
TO WORK FOR ME.
- [bleep] YOU.
AND I ACCEPTED.
HE'S WAITING FOR ME OUTSIDE.
WE'RE GONNA SWING BY
HIS WIGMAKER.
HIS "JUST WOKE UP" HAIR
IS FINALLY READY.
YOU'RE REALLY
GONNA DO THIS?
- IT'S READY, MIKE.
THEY'RE ONLY GONNA HOLD IT
FOR 24 HOURS.
narrator: TOBIAS AND MAEBY,
MEANWHILE,
HAD MAPPED THE ROUTE
TO THE AUDITION.
WELL, HERE WE ARE
AND HOME WE GO,
WITH PLENTY OF TIME
TO GET YOU TO ENGLISH CLASS.
- WAIT.
YOU CAN'T DO A U-TURN
ON YOUR DREAM.
I SAY, WE GET YOU ON THE LOT
AND GET THE FUNKE NAME
OUT THERE,
START TALKING YOU UP
AROUND THE WATER COOLERS.
- OH, MAEBY,
WE'LL NEVER GET ON HERE.
I MEAN, BEHIND THESE WALLS ARE
THE BIGGEST STARS IN THE WORLD,
AMERICA'S TREASURES.
- DAMN IT!
- DAD, YOU'RE AUDITIONING FOR
THE PART OF A CONFIDENCE MAN.
LET'S TRY A LITTLE CONFIDENCE.
- YOU SAY CONFIDENCE MAN?
HEY, I'M UP FOR THAT PART TOO.
- OH.
- GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
- GOOD LUCK TO YOU TOO.
narrator: AS TOBIAS
WAS GAINING SELF-CONFIDENCE,
MICHAEL WAS STRUGGLING
TO KEEP HIS.
- WOW, YOU'RE PRESIDENT AGAIN?
- YES, THIS IS THE WAY
IT SHOULD BE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF WHEN YOU
HEAR THE WORDS, "SUDDEN VALLEY"?
- SALAD DRESSING, I THINK.
BUT FOR SOME REASON,
I DON'T WANNA EAT IT.
- RIGHT.
BUT "PARADISE GARDENS."
- YEAH, OKAY.
I CAN SEE MARINATING A CHICKEN
IN THAT.
UM, I'M ACTUALLY HERE ABOUT
THE SOFTBALL GAME.
WE NEED SOME GIRLS ON THE TEAM,
RIGHT?
- YES, WE DO.
THAT'S A LEAGUE REQUIREMENT.
narrator: ONE THAT WAS DIFFICULT
TO MEET,
GIVEN GOB'S BEHAVIOR
IN THE THIRD INNING
OF LAST YEAR'S GAME.
WE COULD JUST STAY OUT HERE
AND WAIT FOR ANOTHER POP-UP.
narrator:
AND IN THE FIFTH INNING.
- COME ON!
YEAH, HERE WE GO!
narrator:
OH, AND BEFORE THE GAME.
[all cheering]
- WE LOST OUR ENTIRE OUTFIELD
AND A COUPLE OF COURT CASES.
WELL, YOU KNOW
WHO WOULD BE GREAT
AND NOT AT ALL LITIGIOUS IS ANN.
- MMM, NOT ANN.
- NO?
- 'CAUSE, YOU KNOW, THIS--
THIS GAME IS KIND OF OUR THING.
- BUT ANN'S AMAZING.
YOU KNOW, SHE COULD PLAY
MY POSITION.
- YOU SHOULD BE PLAYING
THE FIELD...
THERE, IN RIGHT,
YOU KNOW?
PLUS, I GOT AUNT LINDSAY
PLAYING THIS YEAR.
I CAN'T VERY WELL
PULL HER OFF THE ROSTER.
LET'S MAKE ANN
THE BACKUP, OKAY?
VERY GOOD WAY
TO THINK ABOUT HER, AS A BACKUP.
- SHE'S GONNA BE SO EXCITED.
- GOOD.
- MAYBE--MAYBE NOW
I'LL GET A KISS.
- OKAY.
- OH.
I MEANT FROM ANN.
- YES, I KNOW.
I JUST WANT TO
GET IN THERE FIRST.
- OKAY.
- LINDSAY, WAKE UP.
I NEED YOU TO PLAY ON
THE SOFTBALL TEAM THIS YEAR.
narrator: LINDSAY FELT THE
INTENDED EFFECT OF TEAMOCIL:
A SENSE OF CAMARADERIE.
- COUNT ME IN, MICHAEL.
HAPPY TO HELP THE TEAM.
- GREAT NEWS. I'M BACK.
- YOU JUST LEFT.
- YEAH, I DON'T THINK THINGS
ARE GONNA WORK OUT WITH SITWELL.
I MEAN, WE PICKED UP
HIS SLEEPY-HEAD WIG,
EVERYTHING WAS COOL.
NEXT THING I KNOW,
HE'S ASKING ME
FOR A BUNCH OF WORK IDEAS.
SO, I THOUGHT I'D JUST QUIT
AND GO BACK TO
BEING PRESIDENT HERE.
- I NEED TO DO THIS JOB, OKAY?
I NEED TO PROVE
THAT I CAN DO THIS JOB.
- TO WHO?
- TO...
YOU.
- MICHAEL, I'M YOUR BIG BROTHER.
I'LL NEVER
BE IMPRESSED WITH YOU.
- STILL.
- ANYWAY, LOOK.
YOU CAN STILL DO IT.
I JUST WANT THE OFFICE
AND MY STUFFS AND TITLE.
- WHAT ABOUT...
IF I HELP YOU WITH YOUR WORK
OVER AT SITWELL?
- YOU'D DO THAT?
- SURE.
- YOU REALLY WANT ME
TO SUCCEED AT SITWELL.
- WELL, I JUST--
HEY.
COME ON.
I REALLY WANT YOU TO BE
OVER AT SITWELL.
narrator: LUCILLE WAS WORRIED
THAT HER SON BUSTER
WAS BEING SENT INTO BATTLE
WITH THE ARMY.
- I FEEL THAT WE'VE NOT
BROUGHT SOMETHING UP
THAT MIGHT BE A SOLUTION,
UM, TO SPARE MY FEELINGS.
- SEND YOU IN HIS PLACE?
I CALLED.
THEY DON'T WANT YOU BACK.
narrator: OSCAR HAD SERVED
IN VIETNAM
AS A CROC SPOTTER
ON A SWIFT BOAT.
- CROC!
NO, SORRY. WAIT. LOG.
JUST A LOG.
NO, WAIT. SORRY. CROC!
- IT WAS THERE THAT HE MET
A YOUNG U.S.O. DANCER
NAMED LUCILLE.
- I'D PREFER AN OLDER MAN.
- HEY, I'M FREE AFTER THE SHOW.
- I SAID OLDER, BOB,
NOT DEAD.
- I SWORE I'D NEVER
SAY HIS NAME AGAIN, BUT...
IT'S TIME TO CALL
YOU-KNOW-WHO.
narrator: "YOU-KNOW-WHO"
WAS AN ARMY SERGEANT
NAMED BILL ANDERSON.
HE AND LUCILLE WERE AN ITEM
BEFORE SHE LEFT HIM FOR OSCAR.
AT THE STUDIO,
TOBIAS BEGAN TO CREATE BUZZ
AROUND THE WATER COOLER.
THAT FUNKE IS SOME
KIND OF SOMETHING.
BOY, THIS FUNKE'S ALL ANYBODY'S
EVER TALKING ABOUT.
I'M SO SICK AND TIRED
OF HEARING ABOUT
HOW BRILLIANT THAT FUNKE IS.
OVERRATED.
I'LL JUST MOVE--
I'M SORRY.
OKAY. WE'RE OKAY.
OKAY.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MAEBY LOOKED FOR
AN EMPTY OFFICE
TO CALL GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHERE ARE YOU?
I BOUGHT YOU A DAY.
I CAN'T PUT THIS
BOOK REPORT OFF FOREVER.
- SORRY, IS THIS YOUR OFFICE?
- NO, I'M JUST SITTING BEHIND
SOMEONE ELSE'S DESK
PRETENDING THESE ARE MY KIDS.
CAN YOU GET JUDE LAW
IN HERE FOR A MEETING?
- OH, I'M JUST A READER.
- A READER?
- YEAH.
- I NEED A REPORT BY TOMORROW.
BEFORE GYM--
LUNCH...
WITH JIM...
CARREY.
IT'S THE GRINCH GUY.
YOU'RE TOO YOUNG.
- SO GET THIS.
SITWELL LOVED MY IDEAS.
- WELL, MY IDEAS,
AND I KNEW IT.
THAT'S GREAT.
YOU KNOW, DAD NEVER
COMPLIMENTED ANY OF THOSE.
- HERE'S THE THING.
- I NEED MORE.
- THERE WERE 34 PROPOSALS
IN THERE.
- YOU'D BE AMAZED
HOW FAST THEY COME OUT
WHEN YOU READ THEM ALL
IN A ROW.
- THIRTY-ONE, BAMBOO FLOOR
UPGRADES.
CHEAPER, STRONGER."
I CAN'T READ THIS WORD.
"THIRTY-TWO,
WIRELESS CRAPABILITY."
THAT ONE EXPLAINS ITSELF.
- "THIRTY-THREE,"
- GOB, THAT WAS
SIX MONTHS' WORTH OF WORK.
YOU CAN'T JUST BLURT THEM
ALL OUT AT ONCE.
- MR. BLUTH.
- HE'S COMING.
I'VE GOT TO GO.
- YOU BLEW THEM AWAY.
BOUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
MAYBE WE CAN
PLAY CATCH SOMETIME.
narrator: GOB'S OWN FATHER HAD
ONLY ONCE PLAYED CATCH WITH HIM,
AND IT ENDED AS BADLY
AS ANY GAME OF CATCH COULD END.
- WHITE POWER!
- BETTER YET, MAYBE WE CAN
PLAY BALL ON SATURDAY.
I'LL MEET YOU THERE.
I'VE GOT A NECK HAIR FITTING
AT 11:00.
narrator: GOB WAS BOTH ANGRY...
AND OVERWHELMED
BY THE APPROVAL
FROM THIS NEW FATHER FIGURE.
IT WAS CONFUSING.
MICHAEL WAS LESS TORN
AND WENT TO BRAG TO HIS FATHER.
- SO, APPARENTLY MY IDEAS
AREN'T SO BAD,
AND THAT COMES FROM
SITWELL HIMSELF.
- YOU LET YOUR IDEAS
GO TO SITWELL?
- UH, NO.
I GAVE THEM TO GOB,
WHO, UH, WORKS THERE NOW.
- YOU LET GOB
GO TO SITWELL?
WHAT'D I TELL YOU?
I TOLD YOU--
- "DON'T LET HIM GO."
I KNOW.
BUT MY POINT IS THAT I DO
ALL THE WORK, POP.
- YEAH, AND HE MAKES
ALL THE PLAYS.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
HE WAS THE BEST SOFTBALL PLAYER
IN THE LEAGUE.
narrator:
GOB WAS ESPECIALLY GIFTED
AT SACRIFICING HIS BODY
FOR THE PLAY.
- PLAY'S AT SECOND.
PLAY'S AT SECOND.
YEAH!
SUCK ON THAT, SITWELL.
narrator: ALTHOUGH AT TIMES,
EVEN THAT WASN'T ENOUGH.
- YOUR TWEETY BIRD DANCE
JUST COST US A RUN, YOU MORON.
WHY DO YOU THINK
SITWELL HIRED HIM?
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
YOU'RE GONNA LOSE THE GAME,
AND YOU'RE GONNA LOSE
THE COMPANY--
- THE GAME.
COME ON, WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
IF I WIN THE GAME,
YOU'RE COMFORTABLE WITH ME
RUNNING THE COMPANY?
- YEAH, THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYING.
- I'LL WIN THE GAME.
AND I'LL SHOW HIM THAT HIS
LITTLE PLAN DIDN'T WORK,
ALL RIGHT?
WE CAN BUILD HOUSES.
WE CAN WIN GAMES.
- THAT IS WHAT I WANNA HEAR.
- [crashing sound]
- WE CAN WIN GAMES.
LINDSAY, DID THAT OVEN VENT
HIT YOU?
YOUR FOOT IS BLEEDING.
- MY FOOT IS BLEEDING.
narrator: TEAMOCIL MAY CAUSE
NUMBNESS OF THE EXTREMITIES.
- YOU'RE STILL GONNA BE ABLE
TO PLAY
ON OUR TEAM THIS WEEKEND, RIGHT?
- WHY DO YOU THINK
I'M TAKING TEAMOCIL?
- TO CURB YOUR SEX DRIVE.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT TEAM ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
narrator: IT MAY ALSO CAUSE
SHORT-TERM MEMORY LOSS.
- OKAY, LOOKS LIKE
I'M GONNA NEED
THAT FEMALE BACKUP PLAYER
AFTER ALL.
AND ANN'S REALLY GOOD
AT SOFTBALL, HUH?
- YEAH.
SHE'S AMAZING.
YOU KNOW, SHE'S GOT
THIS LOW CENTER OF GRAVITY.
YOU CAN'T KNOCK HER OVER.
- WELL, I COULD KNOCK HER OVER.
- DAD, I'M TELLING YOU,
YOU CAN'T.
THEY CALL HER "THE WALL,"
YOU KNOW?
WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
BUT I COULD KNOCK HER OVER.
I WON'T, BUT I COULD.
narrator: AND LUCILLE CALLED
ON AN OLD LOVER.
- WILLIAM? -
YES, MA'AM?
- YOU DON'T REMEMBER ME?
narrator:
GENERAL ANDERSON HAD DONE
THREE TOURS OF DUTY IN VIETNAM,
BUT THE ONLY MEMORY HE'D BLOCKED
WAS BEING LEFT BY LUCILLE.
- OH, GOD.
THAT TOUCH.
OH, HOW COULD I FORGET?
PAT.
- LUCILLE.
- I COULD NEVER FORGET
THAT TOUCH.
- BILL, THEY'RE SHIPPING
MY SON BUSTER OFF.
I CAN'T HAVE THAT HAPPEN.
- I'M SORRY.
THERE'S NOTHING I CAN DO.
- IS THERE ANYTHING I CAN DO?
- MAYBE IF YOU...
GO DOWNTOWN.
- OH, I HAVEN'T DONE THAT
IN 30 YEARS.
[singing] WHEN YOU'RE ALONE
AND LIFE IS MAKING YOU LONELY
YOU CAN ALWAYS GO
DOWNTOWN
- YOU MAKE ME WANT TO
PUKE, BLUTH!
narrator: AND SO, BUSTER WAS
PULLED OUT OF COMBAT TRAINING...
- PUT 'EM DOWN
AND HALT!
- AND PUT INTO
U.S.O. TRAINING.
- IT JOLTS.
narrator: AND BACK AT
GOB'S NEW OFFICE...
- IT'S NOT REALLY DOING IT
RIGHT NOW, BUT--
MICHAEL.
- DO YOU STILL NEED THOSE IDEAS?
- COME ON.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
I CAN'T LET SITWELL DOWN.
I-I'M DESPERATE HERE.
- THEN I'LL
MAKE YOU A DEAL.
I WANT YOU TO
THROW THE SOFTBALL GAME.
- NEVER!
HE GAVE ME THIS.
- COURSE HE DID.
WHY DO YOU THINK HE HIRED YOU?
- HE LIKED MY IDEAS.
- THEY WERE MY IDEAS,
AND, NO, HE DIDN'T.
HE JUST WANTS YOU
FOR THE SOFTBALL GAME
BECAUSE HE'S TRYING TO MAKE
OUR FAMILY LOOK FOOLISH.
- I KNEW YOU HAD BAD IDEAS.
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL PLAY HIM.
I'LL THROW THAT SOFTBALL GAME.
NOBODY MAKES A FOOL OF
OUR FAMILY WITHOUT MY HELP.
narrator: TOBIAS HAD TALKED UP
THE NAME FUNKE,
AND IT WAS TIME TO AUDITION.
- WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
- TOBIAS.
- HE'S TOO SHORT.
GIVE IT TO THE GUARD.
- OH. I-I'M NOT--
I--ON CAMERA,
I SEEM MUCH TALLER.
narrator: AND MAEBY PICKED UP
THE READER'S REPORT,
WHICH HAD NOW BECOME
HER BOOK REPORT.
- WHATCHA GOT THERE?
- I CAN'T REALLY DISCUSS IT.
- WELL, IF YOU
WANNA GET IT MADE,
I'M THE GUY WHO HAS TO SEE IT.
YOU'RE THE FUNKE
EVERYONE'S TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT ARE YOU, LIKE, 15?
- MARRY ME.
[laughs]
- EVERYONE THINKS
I LOOK YOUNG TOO.
- SO WHO ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT?
- JUDE LAW.
WHY DO YOU ASK?
- YEAH.
GO YOUNG.
YOUNG GUY AND THE SEA,
BIG SPRING-BREAKER FOR US,
CGI THE FISH.
LET'S FAST-TRACK THIS ONE.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MAEBY REALIZED
SHE HAD BECOME
A SUCCESSFUL FILM EXECUTIVE.
- IT'S ALL WAXED UP.
- ALL WAXED UP?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- I NEED SOMETHING.
A JOB FOR MY DAD.
- YEAH, YEAH.
SURE. OKAY.
- LISTEN TO ME.
BRAND NEW CARS DON'T GET WAXED!
narrator:
THAT AFTERNOON IT WAS GAME TIME,
AND MICHAEL FELT CONFIDENT
ABOUT A BLUTH WIN.
- SPIN, SPIN, SPIN.
narrator: ANN WASN'T AS AMAZING
AS GEORGE MICHAEL
LED HIS FATHER TO BELIEVE.
BUT GOB WAS PLAYING
WORSE THAN EVER,
AS PER HIS AGREEMENT
WITH MICHAEL.
- YOUR GUY CAN'T HIT, SITWELL.
HE'S NEVER GONNA TOUCH IT.
- TIME OUT.
- GOB, ARE YOU OKAY?
- YEAH, I JUST CAN'T HIT TODAY.
GUESS YOU'RE REALLY
DISAPPOINTED IN ME.
- HEY, EVERYBODY
HAS DAYS LIKE THIS.
IT'S ONLY A GAME.
AFTER THAT LIST OF IDEAS
YOU GAVE ME,
I DON'T CARE IF YOU BLOW
THE WHOLE SEASON.
COME HERE, YOU.
OKAY.
WE'RE GOOD.
narrator: AND GOB FINALLY FELT
THAT SOMEONE BELIEVED IN HIM.
EVEN THOUGH
THEY WEREN'T HIS IDEAS.
AND HE DECIDED
TO MAKE SITWELL PROUD.
- GET ON THAT BALL!
- YOU GO!
- YOU BETTER PULL AN ANKLE
OR SOMETHING.
COME ON, GEORGE MICHAEL!
GET THAT BALL IN THERE!
narrator: THEN HE WENT
HEADFIRST INTO THE WALL.
- I'M SAFE.
- YOU'RE OUT!
- OUT? I WAS SAFE!
I'M SAFE!
- STOP WITH THE TWEETY BIRD
DANCE, YOU MORON.
- DAD?
- HE MADE THE CALL.
YOU'RE OUT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- SHUSH, SHUSH, SHUSH.
- DAD?
- HE'S SAFE.
- WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M TAKING CARE OF
WHAT YOU SCREWED UP.
YOU BLEW IT AGAIN, MICHAEL.
- LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING.
I BLEW IT WHEN I LET YOU
START CONTROLLING ME AGAIN.
I EVEN STOOPED TO CHEAT HERE
AT A SOFTBALL GAME.
YOU TWO HAVE BEEN
TALKING TO EACH OTHER.
HOW COME NOBODY CALLED ME?
- WHAT'S GOING ON THERE?
- I'M JUST FIXING SOMETHING
THAT'S BEEN BUGGING ME.
HE WAS SAFE.
HE WAS. WE LOST.
GET OVER IT.
YEAH, AND STAN SITWELL
LIKED MY IDEAS.
HE REALLY BELIEVED IN ME.
- MY IDEAS.
- WELL.
- AND I'M PRESIDENT
WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT, DAD.
I DON'T NEED
YOUR APPROVAL ANYMORE.
- I'M PROUD OF YOU.
- REALLY?
- YEAH. SEE YA.
- MICHAEL, I COULD'VE SWORN
I JUST SAW DAD.
OR NOT.
I THINK HALLUCINATION IS ONE OF
THE SIDE-EFFECTS OF TEAMOCIL.
narrator:
IT ISN'T.
- THANKS FOR MAKING
THE RIGHT CALL THERE, MIKE.
- YEAH.
- SORRY I DIDN'T BLOW THE GAME.
- NO, YOU DID THE RIGHT THING,
AND YOU FINALLY GOT DAD
TO ONE OF YOUR BALL GAMES.
- SCREW HIM.
- YEAH.
- I MISS HIM SO MUCH.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
- MAEBY GETS HER FATHER A JOB.
- I GOT TO FIRE ONE OF YA.
- ANDY RICHTER!
HERE ARE THOSE HEAD SHOTS
I WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT.
- YEAH.
I GOTTA GO.
- IT'S TOBIAS FUNKE.
I TOLD YOU ABOUT THE HEAD SHOTS?
narrator:
AND BUSTER VISITS THE GENERAL.
- I JUST WANTED TO THANK YOU
FOR MY NEW JOB.
[laughs]
WHAT'S WRONG?
- I'M SHIPPING OUT TOMORROW.
- OH, I'VE GOT JUST THE THING.
- OH, I HAVEN'T FELT
HANDS LIKE THAT IN YEARS.
YOU ARE COMING TO THE FRONT.