male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS GETTING READY FOR SCHOOL
WHEN HE CAME ACROSS A BOX
OF LOVE LETTERS HE'D WRITTEN
BUT NEVER SENT
TO HIS COUSIN MAEBY.
ONE LETTER TITLED
"IF YOU WEREN'T MY COUSIN,"
WAS PARTICULARLY INCRIMINATING.
- HEY, PAL, YOU WANT
A RIDE TO SCHOOL?
- UM, NO.
ACTUALLY, I'M--
I'M RIDING WITH THE VEALS,
ANN'S PARENTS.
WELL, YOU DON'T NEED TO BE
ALL PENNED UP WITH THEM.
I'LL DRIVE YOU BOTH.
COME ON, WE'LL TAKE THE STAIRS.
- RIGHT.
HERE'S THE THING THOUGH.
IT'S KIND OF CRAMPED IN THERE.
PLUS, A LOT OF KIDS ARE STILL
TALKING ABOUT
WHEN YOU TOOK DOWN
THAT HOMECOMING BANNER.
- LISTEN, ARE YOU EMBARRASSED
TO BE SEEN IN THAT CAR?
- IT'S NOT A CAR.
BUT--BUT, NO.
- 7I'VE GOT TO GET A NEW CAR.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL DECIDED
TO HIDE THE LOVE LETTERS
IN THE ATTIC,
ALTHOUGH MAEBY
HAD HER OWN PROBLEMS.
AFTER LYING ABOUT HER AGE,
SHE HAD CONNED HER WAY
INTO A JOB
AS A MOVIE STUDIO EXECUTIVE.
- DID YOU GET THE STACK
OF SCRIPTS THAT I SENT YOU?
'CAUSE YOU
CERTAINLY LOOK WELL-RESTED.
- MARRY ME.
- HA!
I NEED YOUR NOTES
ON THOSE TOMORROW.
WANNA HAVE A DRINK?
- YEAH. WHY DON'T WE ASK
YOUR WIFE TO COME WITH US?
- OKAY, THEN.
I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
narrator: AND DOWNSTAIRS,
BUSTER PAID A VISIT.
- HEY, BROTHER.
I NEED A FAVOR.
- OF COURSE YOU DO.
I'M ON FURLOUGH THIS WEEK,
AND EVERYBODY'S OUT DANCING
WITH THEIR GIRL,
AND I'M HOME SITTING WITH MOM.
- MOM DOESN'T WANNA GO DANCING?
I THINK THE AGE DIFFERENCE
IS REALLY STARTING
TO CATCH UP TO US.
- MAYBE IT'S TIME
YOU GOT OUT THERE
AND STARTED MEETING PEOPLE,
YOU KNOW,
MEETIN' WOMEN.
MEETIN' WOMEN WHO DIDN'T GIVE
BIRTH TO YOU.
- MAYBE YOU COULD GO OUT WITH ME
AND HELP ME MEET WOMEN.
- YEAH, THAT'S NOT REALLY
WHAT I MEANT.
I HAVE A VERY BUSY SCHEDULE
RIGHT NOW.
- MY SCHEDULE, HOWEVER,
IS AS OPEN AS MY RELATIONSHIP
WITH MY WIFE.
SO WHY DON'T WE PAIR UP?
AND--AND HIT
THE TOWN TOGETHER.
- OH.
- I'LL BE YOUR WINGMAN.
EVEN IF IT MEANS ME
TAKING A CHUBBY,
I WILL SUCK IT UP.
- BOY, THAT'S ENOUGH
FAMILY STUFF FOR TODAY.
- THAT'S RIGHT, MICHAEL.
GUESS WHO JUST GOT FIRED?
narrator: GOB WAS RECENTLY HIRED
BY THE BLUTH COMPANY'S RIVAL,
SITWELL ENTERPRISES.
AND ALTHOUGH
HE STARTED OFF WELL...
- FIFTY-TWO PERCENT
OF THE COUNTRY IS SINGLE.
THAT'S A MARKET THAT'S BEEN
DOMINATED BY APARTMENT RENTALS.
LET'S TAKE SOME OF THAT MARKET.
I CALL IT "SINGLE CITY."
narrator:
HIS IDEAS FAILED TO EVOLVE.
- IT'S LIKE, "HEY, YOU WANNA
GO DOWN TO THE WHIRLPOOL?"
"YEAH. I DON'T HAVE A HUSBAND."
I CALL IT "SWING CITY."
- LET'S GET INTO SOME NEW AREAS,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
narrator: BUT GOB CONTINUED
TO FINE-TUNE HIS FIRST ONE.
- HOW DO WE FILTER OUT
THE TEASES?
WE DON'T LET THEM IN.
THIS GOES FOR THE GUYS, TOO,
BECAUSE SOMETIMES THE GUYS
ARE TAPPED OUT.
BUT CHECK YOUR LEASE, MAN,
BECAUSE YOU'RE LIVIN'
IN [bleep] CITY.
- YOU'RE FIRED.
- SO GET THIS.
I TOOK HIS DRESS EYEBROWS.
narrator: SITWELL SUFFERED
FROM A DISEASE
THAT RENDERED
HIM COMPLETELY HAIRLESS.
- HE'S NOT GONNA BE HAPPY
ABOUT THAT.
- NO, ESPECIALLY
WHEN HE GOES TO THE OPERA
WITH TWO MUSTACHES
ON HIS FOREHEAD.
OH, BUT THE GOOD NEWS IS:
I'M COMING BACK
TO THE BLUTH COMPANY.
[laughs]
- GOB, WE'RE GETTIN'
ALL JAMMED UP HERE, OKAY?
THE ONLY REASON
THAT YOU WERE PRESIDENT
WAS TO APPEASE THE BOARD.
THEY'VE BEEN APPEASED.
I GOT THE JOB.
- NO, I DON'T
NEED TO BE PRESIDENT.
I JUST LIKED
HAVING AN OFFICE, A TITLE.
- SURE.
- PAYCHECK.
ALSO I NEED A COMPANY CAR.
YOU DO HAVE TO MATCH
SITWELL THERE.
- HANG ON A SEC.
HE GAVE YOU A COMPANY CAR?
- YEAH, AND IT WAS WAY BETTER
THAN ANY OF THE COMPANY CARS
DAD EVER GAVE ME.
- YEAH, RIGHT.
- I MEAN, THE CAMARO WAS OKAY.
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
DAD GAVE YOU THE CAMARO?
I THOUGHT YOU WON THAT
ON "CARD SHARKS."
- MICHAEL, I WAS NEVER
DAD TOLD US NOT TO TELL YOU.
narrator: MICHAEL DECIDED
TO CONFRONT HIS FATHER,
WHO'D BEEN LIVING IN THE ATTIC
SINCE HE'D ESCAPED FROM PRISON.
- DAD?
- OH, THANK GOD YOU'RE HERE.
I'M GOING CRAZY
WITH THE BOREDOM, MICHAEL.
AT LEAST IN PRISON,
WE HAD KNIFE FIGHTS,
AND WE HAD MOVIE NIGHT.
AND ONCE, BOTH.
THOSE MEN DID NOT ENJOY
"SOAPDISH."
I THINK
YOU HAVE TO KNOW THAT WORLD.
- YEAH, LISTEN,
DID YOU BUY A COMPANY CAR
FOR EVERYONE IN THE FAMILY
EXCEPT ME?
- WELL, ACCORDING TO THE BOOKS,
I GAVE YOU FOUR.
I'M SERIOUS.
I'M DRIVING A STAIRCASE,
FOR GOD'S SAKE, OKAY?
IT SMELLS LIKE GAS.
I GET HOP-ONS.
WELL, OF COURSE.
YOU'RE GONNA GET HOP-ONS.
- I PULL DOWN BANNERS,
ALL RIGHT?
AND MOST IMPORTANTLY, DAD,
MY SON DOES NOT LIKE
TO BE SEEN IN IT.
- BUT HE LIKES BEING SEEN
WITH THAT GIRL?
- IT MAKES NO SENSE, I KNOW.
- IT DOESN'T.
I NEVER GAVE YOU
A-A COMPANY CAR.
NO, I GAVE YOU SOMETHING
FAR MORE IMPORTANT.
I GAVE YOU COMPANY,
WHICH, APPARENTLY,
YOU DON'T WANT TO GIVE TO ME.
- YOU'RE NOT LISTENING TO ME.
I'D LOVE TO SIT AND CHAT.
- I'M LONELY UP HERE.
- I'VE GOT TO GET
AN EARLY START,
BECAUSE I'M EXPECTING HEADWINDS
ON THE STAIR CAR.
- YOU SEE ANYBODY HERE?
YOU COULD BRING ME A BOOK.
POP-POP GETS A GRISHAM?
- SO YOU TAKE YOUR MOM
TO WORK EVERY DAY?
BUMMER.
MOMS ARE SUCH A PAIN IN THE ASS,
HUH?
IT'S LIKE "DIE ALREADY!"
[laughs]
- I LOVE MY MOTHER.
- HUH?
- SHE'S ONE OF THE TWO MOST
IMPORTANT PEOPLE IN MY LIFE.
YOU KNOW, SHE AND QUINCY.
narrator: A SPOKESMAN
FOR MR. JONES
DENIES THEY'VE EVER MET,
ALTHOUGH HE COULD NOT EXPLAIN
THE SIX SIGNED GOLD RECORDS
IN STARLA'S APARTMENT.
I COULD NEVER BE WITH A MAN
WHO DOESN'T LOVE HIS MOTHER.
- WOW.
SO, MICHAEL, LISTEN.
I'M HERE TO CONVINCE YOU
TO HIRE ME BACK.
I'M AN IDEAS MAN, MICHAEL.
I THINK I PROVED THAT
WITH [bleep] MOUNTAIN.
LISTEN, I WANT THIS, MICHAEL.
I'M GONNA PROVE TO YOU THAT
I'M WORTHY OF REHIRING
IF IT TAKES EVERY OUNCE OF
DETERMINATION THAT I'VE GOT.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- DID YOU WANT ME TO STAY
AND DO THAT?
- BARRY.
- GOOD NEWS
AND EVEN BETTER NEWS.
YOUR COMPANY'S STOCK
IS UNFROZEN,
AND MY LAWSUIT AGAINST THE
L.A. KINGS IS MOVING FORWARD.
- HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
- MAYBE I STOOD ABOVE
THE PLEXIGLAS
AND A PUCK HIT ME.
IT COULD HAPPEN.
- NO, THE STOCK.
NOW, THAT MEANS WE CAN SELL,
RIGHT?
WE CAN DO
WHATEVER WE WANT WITH IT?
- I'LL TELL YOU ONE THING
YOU DON'T WANT TO DO
IS BUY STOCK
IN THE L.A. KINGS.
- WHAT ABOUT A CAR?
DO YOU THINK I COULD
SELL ENOUGH TO BUY A CAR?
- I THOUGHT YOU HAD FOUR.
OH, YOU MEAN A REAL ONE.
YEAH, SURE.
YOU CAN GET ONE,
AS LONG AS EVERYONE DOESN'T SELL
THE COMPANY STOCK AT ONCE.
YOU DON'T WANT SOMEONE ELSE
TO GET CONTROL OF THE COMPANY.
- RIGHT.
GOT TO KEEP THE COMPANY
INTACT, RIGHT?
THE OTHER PEOPLE
SHOULDN'T RISK SELLING THEIR--
MAYBE YOU CAN DRAFT UP
A LETTER TO THE INVESTORS.
"YES, THE STOCK IS UNFROZEN.
WE URGE YOU NOT TO SELL."
- UH, YEAH.
WH--WHAT YOU JUST SAID
WAS PERFECT.
WHY DO YOU WANT ME TO WRITE IT?
- JUST SEND IT OUT
ON YOUR STATIONERY
AND DO IT QUICKLY.
I HAVE A CAR TO BUY.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MAEBY SNUCK UPSTAIRS
TO SECRETLY READ HER SCRIPTS.
OW!
BACK TO FILM SCHOOL, [bleep].
narrator: AND GEORGE SR.
WAS ONLY TOO HAPPY
TO HAVE SOMETHING TO READ.
- "ARMAGEDDON II: ARMAGEDDON."
THAT'S A BAD TITLE.
[scoffs]
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL WENT TO GET A GOOD DEAL
ON A MODEST COMPANY CAR.
- OH, SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WE HAVE, LIKE, 400 OF THESE.
- I-I DON'T NEED
ANYTHING TOO POPULAR.
- OH, THEY'RE NOT POPULAR.
WE HAVE 400 OF THEM.
- SOLD.
ALTHOUGH, UH,
I'M WONDERING IF MAYBE
IT SHOULD JUST BE
A LITTLE BIT NICER.
I GOT A KID,
IS WHAT I'M THINKING,
AND SAFETY'S KIND OF A FACTOR.
BUT NOTHING TOO FLASHY.
- THIS IS IT, ISN'T IT?
I CAN TELL.
YOU'RE EXCITED.
- I AM.
- I'LL DRAW UP THE PAPERS.
- UNLESS YOU THINK
IT'S TOO DRAB.
- AND IT GETS
VERY GOOD MILEAGE.
- YEAH, WELL, IT, UH...
IT LOOKS LIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT
SO CONCERNED ABOUT MILEAGE.
I SPENT THE LAST 10 YEARS
ON A BIKE,
WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF THE STAIR CAR.
- OH, YOU'RE THE STAIR CAR GUY.
YOU TOOK DOWN OUR BANNER.
- YEAH, SORRY.
I GOT A HOP-ON.
I GOT DISTRACTED.
I HATE THIS.
- I LIKE THESE SUNGLASSES.
THEY COME WITH ANY CAR?
- JUST THIS ONE.
THEY THROW THESE EXTRAS AT YOU
BECAUSE IT'S SO IMPRACTICAL.
NO BACK SEAT.
IT ATTRACTS SO MANY TICKETS.
THE INSURANCE ALONE
COSTS AS MUCH
AS THE LAST THREE CARS WE SAW.
- THE WINDBREAKER?
WINDBREAKER COMES WITH IT TOO?
I GUESS.
I DON'T KNOW.
I'VE NEVER SOLD ONE
OF THESE BEFORE, SO--
- I'LL TAKE IT.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST
INDULGED HIMSELF
WITH AN EXPENSIVE SPORTS CAR...
- AND HERE AGAIN, PLEASE.
- WHILE BUSTER INDULGED
IN A NIGHT OUT WITH TOBIAS.
- THIS PLACE IS EXACTLY
WHAT I HAD HOPED FOR.
ALL LADIES.
- WELL, I'VE HEARD
THAT THIS UNIFORM
IS THE BEST WAY TO MEET--
[gasps]
LUCILLE 2.
- BUSTER!
- SO YOU'RE BACK.
- OH, I'M BACK, BUSTER!
- YEAH.
- AND I AM ROCK STEADY!
NO MORE DIZZIES.
narrator: LUCILLE AUSTERO
HAD JUST RETURNED
FROM A MONTH-LONG STAY
AT A FACILITY
THAT SPECIALIZED
IN THE TREATMENT OF VERTIGO.
- AH.
AH, JUST A MINUTE.
YOU'RE OKAY.
YOU'RE OKAY. YOU'RE OKAY.
WE'RE OKAY.
WE'RE OKAY!
SOMEBODY'LL BE HERE IN A SECOND.
WE'RE OKAY.
I AM STABLE AS A TABLE.
- MM.
- SO, IS THERE A--
A GIRL IN YOUR LIFE?
- [laughs]
WELL, I WOULD HARDLY CALL
MY MOTHER A GIRL,
BUT, YEAH, SHE'S STILL
VERY MUCH A PART OF MY LIFE.
- NO, I MEAN, UH, SOMEONE
WHO MAKES YOU HEAR MUSIC.
- OH, WELL,
SHE MOSTLY LIKES TALK RADIO.
- I MEAN A GIRL WHO
MAKES YOU FEEL ROMANTIC,
AND ALSO WHO MAKES YOU
HEAR BEAUTIFUL MUSIC.
- [laughs]
OH. NO.
- I GUESS WHAT
I'M TRYING TO SAY IS--
- [singing]
START SPREADING THE NEWS
- EVERYBODY THINKS
THEY'RE FRANK SINATRA.
- [singing] I'M LEAVING TODAY
- MAYBE WE COULD START ANEW.
- OH.
narrator: AND LATER, MICHAEL GOT
AN URGENT CALL FROM HIS MOTHER.
- HE'S WITH HER AGAIN.
BUSTER'S TAKEN UP
WITH THAT LUCILLE 2.
- THAT'S WHY YOU
CALLED ME HERE?
I'VE GOT MY SECRETARY
BRINGING OVER
A BUNCH OF IMPORTANT PAPERS
BECAUSE I THOUGHT
THIS WAS URGENT.
- WELL, IT'S ALL YOUR FAULT.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO INSISTED
HE GET AWAY FROM MOTHER.
- WELL, I WASN'T TRYING
TO SEND HIM TO A NEW ONE.
WHERE IS HE?
- HE'S ON THE BALCONY.
- BUSTER?
- MOM'S BECOMING
A LITTLE CONTROLLING.
- WHAT TIPPED YOU OFF?
WHEN SHE LOCKED YOU OUT
ON THE BALCONY AGAIN?
- THAT WAS HALF MY FAULT.
I THOUGHT I SAW A GRAHAM CRACKER
OUT THERE.
- YOU BAITED THE BALCONY?
PROVE IT.
- SO I DON'T TYPICALLY
TAKE SIDES WITH MOTHER,
BUT I-I-I DO AGREE
THAT LUCILLE 2
MIGHT NOT BE
THE BEST CHOICE FOR YOU.
- I WOULDN'T EVEN
HAVE BEEN THERE
IF MOM WANTED TO GO BOWLING.
HOW AM I GONNA MEET SOMEONE
WHO HAS MY INTERESTS?
- HI, MICHAEL.
- HEY. GREAT.
- I HAVE THOSE PAPERS
FOR YOU TO SIGN.
- PERFECT.
- BY THE WAY,
I LOVE YOUR MOTHER.
- OH, YEAH, I DO TOO.
- OH.
- I THINK I MAY HAVE FOUND
A NEW GIRL FOR BUSTER.
- GOOD.
THAT LUCILLE ISN'T REALLY
INTERESTED IN BUSTER ANYWAY.
SHE'S JUST TRYING
TO GET EVEN WITH ME.
- GET EVEN WITH YOU FOR WHAT?
- SHE WANTED ME TO LET IN
HER REMODELING CREW
WHILE SHE WAS OUT OF TOWN.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS TUB'S A LITTLE BIGGER
THAN IT USED TO BE.
narrator: IT WAS.
INSTEAD OF LETTING
THE CONSTRUCTION CREW
INTO LUCILLE AUSTERO'S
PENTHOUSE...
- COME RIGHT IN.
narrator: LUCILLE HAD PUT THEM
TO WORK ON A PROJECT OF HER OWN.
- WHAT'D YOU DO?
- WELL, I SAT ON ONE
OF THESE JETS.
BUT I THINK WE CAN FIX IT.
- DON'T GIVE ME THAT LOOK.
I MOVED THE WALL A COUPLE
OF INCHES INTO HER PENTHOUSE.
DON'T THINK SHE'S NOT
OVER THERE RIGHT NOW,
PLOTTING HER REVENGE.
- GOD, THE NEW EQUILIBRIUM
REALLY DOES--
IT MAKES THE ROOM
SEEM TIGHTER.
- SHE'S ALWAYS A STEP
AHEAD OF ME.
- THAT'S WHAT MAKES HER
SUCH A WORTHY OPPONENT.
- HOW'D YOU PAY FOR IT?
- I CASHED IN SOME STOCK.
YOU KNOW IT WAS UNFROZEN.
I KNOW.
I SENT YOU THAT LETTER.
IT SAYS NOT TO SELL,
OR WE'RE GONNA LOSE CONTROL.
- IT DOES?
I STOPPED AT "UNFROZEN."
- LINDSAY, YOU DIDN'T CASH IN
YOUR STOCK, DID YOU?
TELL ME YOU DIDN'T.
- I DIDN'T.
narrator: YET.
- THERE'S A PRETTY LONG
WAIT LIST
FOR MEMBERSHIP RIGHT NOW.
- GOB, YOU DIDN'T SELL,
DID YOU?
- WHAT?
NO.
I'M TRYING TO GET A JOB
FROM YOU, MIKEY.
COME ON.
- OKAY, AS LONG AS YOU TWO
DIDN'T SELL,
I THINK WE SHOULD BE OKAY.
- I WAS AFRAID THAT I--
- I JUST BOUGHT THE QUEEN MARY.
- YOU'RE KIDDING.
I WAS JUST GONNA GET A YACHT.
- NO, NO, NO.
THE CLUB.
I WAS DANCING WITH WHAT TURNED
OUT TO BE THE CLUB'S OWNER,
AND HE WAS LOOKING TO SELL.
OH, HE REALLY, REALLY
DID LOOK LIKE A WOMAN.
BUT ANYHOO, CAN YOU BELIEVE
THAT THE ONLY REASON
THE CLUB IS GOING UNDER
IS BECAUSE IT'S IN
A TERRIFYING NEIGHBORHOOD?
- THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE.
- TOBIAS, I PROMISED THAT MONEY
TO THE COUNTRY CLUB.
- COUNTRY CLUB?
- IT'S IN SUCH
A GOOD NEIGHBORHOOD.
- I DON'T BELIEVE THIS.
DID YOU GUYS
NOT READ THE LETTER?
narrator: NONE OF THEM HAD READ
PAST THE WORD "UNFROZEN."
- I HOPE YOU'RE ALL
PROUD OF YOURSELVES.
YOUR CARELESS,
SELFISH SPENDING SPREES
MAY HAVE COST US
THE BLUTH COMPANY.
- HEY, DAD, IS THAT
YOUR NEW CAR IN THE DRIVEWAY?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU GOT A CORVETTE!
- IT'S A COMPANY CAR.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD BOUGHT A CAR,
AND IT HAD HELPED
PUT THE COMPANY IN JEOPARDY.
- I'M SORRY ABOUT THE PATCH.
I'M TESTIFYING AGAINST
THE KINGS THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT.
I JUST WINKED.
SO BASICALLY, YOU'RE ABOUT
2,000 SHARES SHORT
OF BEING
THE MAJORITY STOCKHOLDERS.
NOW, UNFORTUNATELY,
IT'S A PRIVATE STOCK,
SO YOU CANNOT JUST BUY UP
THE SHARES
UNLESS SOMEONE
IS WILLING TO SELL.
- ARE YOU SURE?
- THAT'S WHAT THEY SAID
ON ASK JEEVES.
- ALL RIGHT, WHO'S
THE MAJORITY SHAREHOLDER NOW?
- A COMPANY CALLED STANDPOOR.
- STANDPOOR?
- AS IN THE OPPOSITE OF SITWELL,
WHICH IS RUN BY
A CERTAIN HAIRLESS MAN
WHO COULD BE VERY UPSET WITH YOU
RIGHT NOW.
- WHAT WOULD HE HAVE TO BE UPSET
WITH ME ABOUT?
- YOU'RE WEARING HIS EYEBROWS?
- THEY MAKE ME FEEL DRESSIER.
[telephone rings]
- HELLO?
- IS IT TRUE, MICHAEL?
DID WE LOSE THE COMPANY?
- KIND OF.
TO SOMETHING CALLED
STANDPOOR.
YEAH, IT'S SITWELL.
- IT'S LUCILLE AUSTERO.
- LUCILLE 2?
- STANDPOOR, BECAUSE SHE CAN'T
STAND UP WITHOUT FALLING OVER.
I DON'T KNOW WHY SHE'D HAVE
ANY TROUBLE.
A PIANO COULD STAND
ON THOSE LEGS.
SHE'S TRYING TO GET EVEN WITH ME
FOR THE REMODELING.
- I THINK WE'RE GONNA NEED
A NEW FLOATING THERMOMETER.
COULD I HAVE YOUR--
YOUR BLUE CROSS NUMBER?
- WELL, LET'S THINK ABOUT THIS,
MOM.
I MEAN, MAYBE THERE'S A WAY
THAT WE CAN REASON WITH HER.
- GIVE HER BUSTER.
- WHAT?
- WE NEED OUR COMPANY BACK.
- MOM, THAT'S HORRIBLE.
- I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'VE SPENT MONEY
ON SOMETHING YOU CAN RETURN?
- LET'S GIVE HER BUSTER.
- STARLA, DO YOU KNOW
WHERE MY BROTHER IS?
- YES, HE'S ON CLOUD NINE.
THAT WAS ME, MICHAEL.
- WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHERE'S STARLA?
- OH, SHE'S SAYING GOOD-BYE
TO SOMEONE NAMED Q.
IF SHE CAN GET PAST
HIS SECURITY SYSTEM,
SHE'S GONNA TELL HIM IT'S OVER.
SHE'S AMAZING.
[laughs]
WE COMPLETELY CONNECTED,
AND IT'S ALL BECAUSE OF YOU.
YOU MADE THIS HAPPEN.
I FEEL ALIVE!
narrator: INDEED, STARLA AND
BUSTER DID HIT IT OFF WELL,
BUSTER BEING A SWEETER,
MORE SUPPORTIVE MAN
THAN SHE WAS USED TO,
AND STARLA BEING A WOMAN
THAT WASN'T 70.
- I'M JUST WONDERING
IF YOU DIDN'T UPGRADE
A LITTLE TOO FAST.
YOU KNOW,
YOU WANT SOMETHING SENSIBLE,
YOU END UP GETTING
PUSHED INTO SOMETHING FLASHY.
- [whispering]
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
- DON'T YOU THINK
YOU BELONG IN A LUCILLE?
[stairs rattling]
narrator: MAEBY, MEANWHILE,
GAVE READING HER SCRIPT
ANOTHER SHOT,
ONLY TO DISCOVER
HER WORK WAS DONE.
HER SCRIPTS HAD BEEN NOTED.
SO SHE WENT TO FIND THE PERSON
SHE THOUGHT WAS RESPONSIBLE.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
I READ YOUR NOTES.
- WHAT?
YOU--
OH, YOU FOUND THE--
WELL, LOOK, I DON'T--
THAT WAS A LONG--
- THEY WERE GREAT.
I MEAN, THEY SAID SO MANY THINGS
I WANTED TO SAY,
BUT I DIDN'T KNOW HOW,
YOU KNOW?
DON'T TELL ANYONE, OKAY?
- NEVER.
- I GUESS SHE DIDN'T
SEE THE DRAWINGS.
narrator: MEANWHILE, TOBIAS
PREPARED TO ASSUME OWNERSHIP
OF THE QUEEN MARY.
- IT'S SUPPOSED TO SAY
"TOBIAS'S QUEEN MARY."
NO, THAT IS NOT WHAT IT SAYS.
I DISTINCT--
HELLO?
WELL, I SUPPOSE I COULD JUST
PAINT OVER "MARY."
- DON'T BOTHER, MAN.
THIS IS OUR CLUB NOW.
narrator: TOBIAS DIDN'T WANT TO
SELL HIS NEW CLUB,
BUT LINDSAY DID.
WHICH IS WHY SHE HIRED
SEVERAL MEMBERS
OF A LOCAL STRIPPER AGENCY,
CALLED THE HOT COPS,
TO POSE AS THE ROUGHNECKS.
- ALL RIGHT, FELLAS, LOOK.
I KNOW YOU KNOW NOTHING
BUT A LIFE ON THE STREET,
BUT I'D LIKE TO
OFFER YOU SOMETHING
THAT THE QUEEN MARY GAVE ME:
THE JOY OF THE STAGE.
SO MAYBE YOU COULD, UH,
START JETE-ING
AND STOP "JE-TERRORIZING" ME.
- YEAH!
- ABSOLUTELY!
- WE COULD DO "RENT."
- WELL, THIS IS JOYOUS NEWS.
narrator: AND BUSTER,
NOW CONVINCED THAT LUCILLE 2
WAS THE RIGHT WOMAN FOR HIM,
BROKE UP WITH STARLA.
- YOU OKAY?
- IT WAS FOR THE BEST ANYWAY.
A GIRL LIKE THAT DESERVES
TO BE TAKEN CARE OF,
AND I'M JUST A POOR SOLDIER.
- YOU DIDN'T SELL YOUR STOCK?
- WHAT?
NO.
YOUR LETTER SAID NOT TO,
AND I WOULD NEVER
WANT TO HURT THE FAMILY.
narrator: AND MICHAEL REALIZED
HIS LITTLE BROTHER
DESERVED HAPPINESS
MORE THAN ANYONE.
YOU KNOW, I WANT YOU
TO FORGET ABOUT WHAT I SAID.
I WAS WRONG.
YOU TWO BELONG TOGETHER.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF LUCILLE 2 FOR YOU.
- REALLY?
- YEAH.
- LET HER DOWN EASY.
THAT RIGHT KNEE
COULD GO AT ANY TIME.
STARLA!
narrator: AND AT THE
"TOBIAS IS QUEEN MARY,"
TOBIAS COULDN'T BELIEVE HOW
QUICKLY HE HAD GOTTEN THROUGH
TO HIS RAGTAG GANG
OF NEIGHBORHOOD TOUGHS.
- WOW.
YOU REALLY HAVE MADE
SOME AMAZING STRIDES
IN A HALF AN HOUR.
WE HAVE TO TAKE THIS
TO THE STREETS.
WE HAVE TO STRUT!
narrator: MICHAEL KNEW
IF HE HAD ANY CHANCE
OF GETTING CONTROL
OF THE COMPANY AGAIN,
HE WOULD NEED TO CHARM
LUCILLE 2.
- YOUR HAIR.
- CAN I TAKE YOU FOR A SPIN?
narrator: BUT THE SPIN
IN MICHAEL'S NEW CAR
RETRIGGERED HER VERTIGO.
THAT NIGHT, TOBIAS'S PLAN
TO CHANGE THE STREETS
WITH HIS GANG
ALSO TURNED OUT
TO BE ILL-CONCEIVED.
- HEY, "FEZELLAS," LOOKS LIKE
YOU GUYS ARE UP TO NO GOOD.
WELL, THIS GANG USED TO BE
LIKE THAT TOO,
THREE, FOUR!
[rapping]
SO YOU THINK YOU'RE TOUGH
WELL, WE HATE RAPPIN'
BUT DON'T BUST A CAP IN
'CAUSE HERE'S WHAT'S HAPPENIN'
WE'RE BREAKIN' OUT
SOME OLD-FASHIONED TAPPIN'
[all singing]
HEY BLOODS AND CRIPS
THERE'S A NEW GANG IN TOWN
- OH, I'VE BEEN SHOT!
- WE MISCALCULATED!
RETREAT!
- QUICK, SWITCH TO FOLLIES!
- THAT'S NOT GONNA HELP!
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL AND LUCILLE 2 ARRIVED
TO FIND THE CLUB NEARLY EMPTY,
ALTHOUGH MICHAEL
WOULD HAVE FIT IN PERFECTLY.
- IT'S PROBABLY--
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT, LUCILLE.
I'M GONNA TAKE YOU
DANCING, HUH?
- NO, MICHAEL, PLEASE.
YOU HAVE UNDONE ALL OF
DR. SANDOR PLUMB'S WORK.
- OH, I'M SORRY.
LOOK, THE REASON
THAT I SHOWED UP TONIGHT
WAS BECAUSE I DON'T THINK
THAT IT'S RIGHT
FOR YOU TO BE DATING MY BROTHER.
I MEAN, HE'S MET SOMEONE ELSE,
AND, FRANKLY,
THE ONLY REASON THAT
HE ASKED YOU OUT TONIGHT
WAS BECAUSE I WANTED HIM TO GET
THE STOCK BACK FROM YOU
SO THAT I COULD REGAIN
CONTROL OF THE COMPANY.
BUT I WOULD--
I'D RATHER HAVE MY BROTHER BACK.
SO, I'M SORRY.
- I UNDERSTAND.
- THANK YOU.
AND I DO NOT BLAME YOU FOR
NOT LIKING THE BLUTHS ANYMORE.
- LIKE THE BLUTHS?
I LOVE THE BLUTHS.
- WHY DID YOU BUY UP
ALL OF OUR COMPANY STOCK?
- TO SUPPORT YOU GUYS.
I HAVE ALWAYS HAD
A STANDING ORDER
TO BUY UP
ANY AVAILABLE BLUTH STOCK.
- YOU DO KNOW THAT WE'RE ABOUT
2,000 SHARES SHORT
OF CONTROLLING THE COMPANY NOW,
THOUGH.
- WELL, YOU COULD HAVE
SOME OF MINE.
REALLY?
WOULD YOU DO THAT?
- YEAH, OF COURSE.
- WELL, THAT'S--
THANK YOU.
- ACTUALLY,
THERE IS A CONDITION.
- ANYTHING.
- CALL ME A CAB.
- AH, BECAUSE OF MY DRIVING.
YES.
narrator:
AND SO THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL WAS THRILLED TO HAVE
CONTROL OF THE COMPANY BACK.
- I FIXED EVERYTHING.
- OH?
- WITH THE BUSINESS.
IT'S ALL TAKEN CARE OF.
- YOU DIDN'T THINK I COULD,
BUT I DID.
- GOB, WHAT'D YOU DO?
narrator: GOB HAD
RUN INTO LUCILLE 2
SHORTLY AFTER MICHAEL
DROPPED HER OFF.
MY MOM REALLY TOOK UP
A BUNCH OF YOUR SPACE, HUH?
WHAT A BITCH.
- WHAT--WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- WHEN SHE EXPANDED HER BATHROOM
AND MOVED YOUR WALL OVER.
THAT'S WHY ALL YOUR STUFF'S
STICKING OUT.
- OH.
YOUR MOTHER REALLY HAS A WAY
OF GETTING MY GOAT.
[laughter]
narrator:
SO GOB [bleep] LUCILLE 2.
- YOU WHAT?
- OH, AND SHE'S NOT GONNA
GIVE THE SHARES BACK NOW.
YOU JUST SAID THAT
YOU FIXED EVERYTHING.
- OH, I MEANT MY PROBLEMS.
YEAH, SHE'S GONNA MAKE ME
THE NEW PRESIDENT.
BUT YOU DON'T NEED TO PROVE
YOURSELF TO ME, LITTLE BROTHER.
YOU WILL ALWAYS
HAVE A JOB HERE.
BUT I DO NEED THE KEYS
TO THE COMPANY CAR.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT,"
LUCILLE 2 RECLAIMS
SOME SPACE.
THE QUEEN MARY
CHANGES HANDS ONCE AGAIN.
- I-I'VE WANTED
A SMALL FAMILY RESTAURANT
SINCE I GOT
THE KINGS SETTLEMENT.
IT STILL HAS
THE DUNGEON AREA, RIGHT?
narrator:
AND GOB GETS NEEDY.
- OH.
- LET'S GO FOR IT.