male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH
WAS WORKING AT HOME
WHEN HIS SON
MADE A CURIOUS REQUEST.
- DAD, WOULD ANYONE
MISS THIS
PETER AND THE WOLF
READ-ALONG RECORD?
- NO, ACTUALLY,
I THINK THAT'S PART OF
THE MODEL HOME DECORATIONS.
WHY?
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
MY GIRLFRIEND ANN WANTS TO HAVE
A CHRISTIAN MUSIC BONFIRE HERE.
- THAT SOUNDS LIKE
SOME MILD FUN.
I THINK WE'VE GOT
SOME CHRISTMAS MUSIC.
- OH, NO. IT'S NOT--IT'S NOT
A "CHRISTIAN MUSIC" BONFIRE.
IT'S A CHRISTIAN
"MUSIC BONFIRE."
YOU KNOW, WE BURN
ALL SATANIC MUSIC.
THE THING IS, THOUGH,
THE ONLY MUSIC I HAVE
IS EITHER INSTRUCTIONAL
OR HUMOR.
narrator: HE'D BEEN PARTICULARLY
FOND OF A CD
OF SOMETHING CALLED
THE JERKY BOYS.
- HELLO.
- HEY, NITZ.
HEY, JERKY.
I WANT TO BUY A HOUSE, DAD.
IT'S GOT TO BE BIG.
- YOU--YOU SAID "DAD," BUDDY.
- SHUT UP, JERKY.
[dial tone]
- [laughing]
- HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL,
JESUS CALLED.
HE WANTS YOUR "THRILLER" ALBUM.
- YEAH, I DON'T THINK THE
BONFIRE IS SUCH A GREAT IDEA.
- I KNOW IT MIGHT BE WEIRD,
BUT ANN'S MY GIRLFRIEND,
SO I THINK I'LL GO
BUY SOME ALBUMS TODAY.
HEY, CAN YOU COVER FOR ME
AT THE BANANA STAND IF I--
- NO.
- I'LL COVER FOR YOU, PAL.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE I'VE BEEN DOWN
AT THAT BANANA STAND.
- OH, OKAY.
GOOD.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY WE'RE EVER
GONNA GET IT AIR-CONDITIONED.
- MICHAEL!
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO OWE YOU A FAVOR?
I WANT YOU TO BID ON ME AT
THE CHARITY AUCTION THIS YEAR.
- OKAY, NOW I'D LIKE TO USE UP
MY FAVOR AND DECLINE.
- [sighs]
- AND ISN'T THAT
BUSTER'S ANNUAL JOB?
- YES, BUT I CAN'T HAVE
A REPLAY OF LAST YEAR.
narrator: WHEN BUSTER
INADVERTENTLY BID ON LUCILLE 2.
- $10,000!
- BUSTER.
- [shrieks]
- AND YOU'RE EMBARRASSED
TO HAVE OSCAR BID ON YOU.
- WITH HIS TWO PAIR OF PANTS?
YOU BET.
- OH, HI, MOM.
I HAVE THE AFTERNOON FREE.
- REALLY?
DID NOTHING CANCEL?
- ALL RIGHT.
I NEED TO BORROW A FUR.
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE ANTIFUR,
LINDSAY.
IN FACT, WEREN'T YOU PROTESTING
SOME HUNTER GUN THING YESTERDAY?
- I STOPPED BY.
I HADN'T CHOSEN A SIDE.
- MURDERERS!
YOU'RE ALL MURDERERS!
- THERE ARE PLENTY OF RULES
ABOUT GUNS ALREADY ON THE BOOKS.
YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED
TO SELL A GUN TO A KID.
YOU'RE NOT EVEN ALLOWED
TO FIRE YOUR GUN IN THE AIR...
- ISN'T THAT FRANK WRENCH?
- ON THE FOURTH OF JULY.
narrator: IN FACT, IT WAS
PEOPLE'S CHOICE NOMINATED ACTOR
MOSES TAYLOR,
FAMOUS FOR HIS PORTRAYAL
OF THE RULE-ABIDING DETECTIVE...
- STOP SIGN.
narrator: FRANK WRENCH.
STAR OF THE TELEVISION SHOW
"WRENCH."
- WELL, THAT'S ONE RULE
I'M NOT GONNA FOLLOW.
[crowd screams]
THAT'S THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
READ IT.
- WHAT DO YOU NEED
WITH ONE OF MOM'S FURS?
- I'M COLD.
- SO AM I.
- NO.
- ALL RIGHT, LOOK.
I MET MOSES TAYLOR.
WE'RE HAVING A DATE
IN THE PARK TOMORROW.
TRY TO GET HIM TO BID ON YOU
AT THE AUCTION TOMORROW,
BECAUSE MICHAEL CAN'T.
HE'S BIDDING ON MOTHER.
- EXCEPT THAT I'M NOT.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I'M GONNA GO WORK
IN THE BANANA STAND.
- AND I'M GONNA SEE IF I CAN
GET A WRENCH TO STRIP MY NUTS.
I WAS TRYING TO BE SEXY.
IT JUST GOT AWAY FROM ME.
- IT'S BACHELORETTE SEASON
IN NEWPORT BEACH,
AND SOME LOVELY LADIES
ARE UP FOR AUCTION.
PLUS, ANOTHER WOLF SIGHTING
IN THE PARK.
WHAT THAT MEANS
FOR YOUR WEEKEND.
- BAD NEWS, MICHAEL.
I'M AFRAID THE BLUE MAN GROUP
AND I HAVE PARTED WAYS.
SEEMS I'M OFFICIALLY NO LONGER
A STANDBY UNDERSTUDY.
- "CEASE AND DESIST."
- SEEMS THEY DON'T
APPRECIATE COMPETITION.
narrator: TOBIAS HAD RECENTLY
TAKEN OUT AN AD
IN A TRADE MAGAZINE
FOR A ONE-MAN SHOW.
- AND THE WORST PART
IS LINDSAY'S OUT THERE
CHASING SOME SUCCESSFUL ACTOR.
TELEVISION'S FRANK WRENCH.
I NEED TO PROVE TO HER
THAT I'M NOT JUST A MAN,
BUT A MAN'S MAN.
- WELL, I THINK SHE KNOWS THAT.
[wolflike howling]
- JESUS! IT'S THE WOLF!
THAT IS THE WOLF!
THE WOLF IS UPSTAIRS!
- I THINK IT'S JUST MY SON'S
PETER AND THE WOLF RECORD.
- I THOUGHT THAT WAS
A HOMEFILL.
narrator: MICHAEL WENT
TO CHECK ON HIS FUGITIVE FATHER,
WHO WAS LIVING IN THE ATTIC.
- YOU HEARD MY CALL?
- HAVE YOU BEEN DOING THAT
ALL OVER TOWN?
BECAUSE PEOPLE THINK THAT
THERE'S A WOLF ON THE LOOSE.
- YES, THERE IS A WOLF
ON THE LOOSE,
AND HIS NAME IS OSCAR.
TELL ME HE'S NOT GONNA BE
BIDDING ON YOUR MOTHER
AT THAT CHARITY AUCTION
WITH MY MONEY.
- IS THAT WHY YOU
CALLED ME UP HERE, DAD?
BECAUSE YOU ARE A FUGITIVE,
AND AS FAR AS SHE KNOWS,
YOU'RE IN ANOTHER COUNTRY.
- IT'S DRIVING ME CRAZY.
THEY'RE PARADING IN PUBLIC.
MY BACK IS--IT'S IN KNOTS.
I HAVEN'T HAD A MASSAGE
SINCE PRISON.
- HOPE THAT WAS FORCED.
- BUT THEN I FOUND A WAY TO
FIX MY BACK IN THIS OLD CATALOG.
LOOK AT THIS HOT TUB.
I COULD USE IT
FOR SO MANY THINGS.
IT COULD BE MY, YOU KNOW,
WATER SUPPLY.
AND THOSE, UH, PREMADE
BOIL-IN-BAG MEALS--
YOU JUST TOSS THOSE IN THERE.
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING
A HOT TUB.
- AH, COME ON.
PLEASE!
- DAD, PLEASE.
WE CAN'T AFFORD THAT.
WE'RE IN THIS MESS
BECAUSE OF YOU.
I'M WORKING DOWN AT
THE BANANA STAND
JUST SO THAT WE DON'T
LOSE A SHIFT.
WE'RE DONE PAMPERING OURSELVES
IN THIS FAMILY.
YEAH, I WOULD LIKE THE BIGGEST
AIR-CONDITIONER YOU'VE GOT.
NO, NO, NOT TOMORROW.
I NEED--
I NEED IT TODAY.
I'M NOT HERE TOMORROW.
narrator: JUST THEN,
MICHAEL RAN INTO A WOMAN
WHOM HE HADN'T SEEN IN YEARS.
- MICHAEL?
- SALLY SITWELL.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD ALWAYS
BEEN IN LOVE WITH SALLY SITWELL.
- WE COULD STEAL A GOLF CART.
- NO, THEY KEEP 'EM
LOCKED UP.
I KNOW, 'CAUSE I HAVE A KEY.
- I'LL GO GET MY SWEATER.
- OH, SO YOU WANNA
USE THE KEY.
narrator: BUT HIS FATHER
HAD A LONGTIME COMPETITION
WITH HER FATHER.
IT LOOKS LIKE MY BOY IS GONNA BE
STICKING IT TO YOUR DAUGHTER,
SITWELL.
STICK IT TO HER.
narrator: AS A RESULT,
MICHAEL WAS AWKWARD AROUND HER.
- SHOULD WE GO OR...
STICK AROUND?
NO, WE'RE NOT GONNA BE
STICKING ANYTHING,
NOT--NOT GONNA STICK A THING.
narrator: SINCE THEN,
HE'D ALWAYS BEEN EAGER
TO SHOW HER
THAT HE'D BECOME A MAN.
- ARE YOU STILL WORKING HERE?
- NO, NO, NO.
FILLING IN FOR MY SON.
- MICHAEL, AND--
WOW.
SALLY.
STICKWELL.
- RIGHT.
BECAUSE THE GUYS WANTED TO
STICK IT TO ME.
- WHAT? NO.
- I NEVER--
- MICHAEL USED TO SAY THAT.
- NO, I DID NOT.
- WELL, YOU SAID OTHER STUFF.
- I ABSOLUTELY DID NOT SAY THAT.
- MAN, HE LOVED YOU.
- SO, GOB, TELL ME,
ARE YOU STILL DOING
YOUR LITTLE TRICKS?
DO YOU CONSIDER THIS
TO BE A LITTLE TRICK?
- OH.
DID YOU JUST SQUIRT ME
WITH SOMETHING?
- IT'S LIGHTER FLUID.
DIDN'T PUT IN A NEW FLINT.
BUT STILL, WHERE DID
THE LIGHTER FLUID COME FROM?
- WELL, THAT'S [bleep] GREAT.
- MICHAEL, MAYBE I'LL SEE YOU
OVER AT THE CLUB.
WE NEVER REALLY TOOK
THAT CART RIDE, DID WE?
- AND WE NEVER WILL,
'CAUSE I'M NOT THERE.
NOR AM I HERE.
I MEAN, I'M HERE TODAY.
- I'M GONNA GO.
- OKAY.
- SMOOTH, MICHAEL,
LIKE HER FATHER'S HEAD,
CHEST, ARMS, LEGS, AND ASS.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
- HE'S HAIRLESS, MICHAEL.
IT'S A CONDITION.
I HATE THE GUY,
BUT AT LEAST HE'S GOT [bleep].
SATINY AND SMOOTH, PROBABLY.
- WELL, I'M JUST DIFFERENT
THAN YOU, GOB.
I'M NOT GONNA, YOU KNOW, SIPHON
GAS OUT OF SOME GIRL'S CAR
LIKE YOU USED TO IN HIGH SCHOOL,
JUST SO YOU CAN SHOW UP
AND SAY,
"CAR TROUBLES?"
- IT'S CALLED TAKING ADVANTAGE.
IT'S WHAT GETS YOU AHEAD
IN LIFE.
- LIKE YOU DID WITH OUR BIGGEST
SHAREHOLDER, LUCILLE AUSTERO.
- THAT WAS A ONE-TIME THING,
MICHAEL.
IT'S OVER.
narrator:
IT WAS FAR FROM OVER.
- SHALL I PUT THE POSTUREPEDIC
IN THE DOWN POSITION?
- LET'S ELEVATE THE KNEES
THIS TIME.
[laughter]
AND YOU JUST LET
SALLY SITWELL SLIP AWAY
RIGHT WHEN SHE
WAS READY TO GO,
AND YOU WERE SCARED.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- [clucking]
- COME ON.
YOU GONNA GET OFF
AND DO YOUR LITTLE DANCE TOO?
- NO, I...
HURT MY ANKLE YESTERDAY
SHOOTING HOOPS OR SOMETHING.
[clucking]
OH, GOD.
MY ANKLE.
- DON'T MOVE.
LET ME--
- NO, NO, NO.
IT'S BAD. IT'S BAD.
- MOTHER! MOTHER!
- BUSTER, IT HURTS.
narrator: MICHAEL DECIDED
THAT PERHAPS
HE SHOULD GO AFTER SALLY.
HAVE YOU SEEN
MY OTHER PAIR OF PANTS?
- LUPE WASHED THEM,
AND THEY SPROUTED.
I THREW THEM OUT.
- WELL, THAT PUTS A LOT
OF PRESSURE ON THIS PAIR.
- I THINK THIS ONE'S GOOD.
LOOKS LIKE IT WOULD'VE
PUT UP A FIGHT.
- I PUT UP ONE TO GET IT.
- HEY, AS LONG AS IT GETS
FRANK WRENCH TO BID ON ME.
- IT WON'T.
- HEY, MOM.
I NEED TO BORROW
YOUR COUNTRY CLUB CARD.
THERE'S A FRIEND I HAVE
THAT HAS LUNCH THERE OFTEN
I'D LIKE TO RUN INTO.
- SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE ASKING
FOR A FAVOR.
- AND I KNOW WHAT THAT'S GONNA
COST ME.
I'M WILLING TO BID ON YOU.
- I'LL GIVE YOU THE MONEY.
START AT FIVE GRAND.
IF THERE ARE OTHER BIDDERS,
BACK OFF GRACEFULLY.
SHOUT OUT, "I GET HER 364 DAYS
A YEAR FOR FREE!"
OR SOMETHING.
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA HEAR
THAT PHRASE.
narrator: SOON,
TOBIAS CAME ACROSS A FLYER
THAT PROMISED TO IMPROVE
BOTH HIS MASCULINE SELF-IMAGE
AND HIS FINANCIAL STANDING.
- THEY'RE LITERALLY BLUE,
NOT SAD.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL WENT TO HAVE
HIS ACCIDENTAL ENCOUNTER
WITH SALLY,
BUT HAD FORGOTTEN ABOUT
THE CLUB'S DRESS CODE FOR LUNCH.
- I CAN'T WEAR THIS.
I LOOK LIKE I'M 16.
- MICHAEL?
- OH, NO.
- HELLO, MICHAEL.
- STAN.
HELLO, SALLY.
- HI.
SO, ARE YOU MEETING SOMEONE
HERE FOR LUNCH?
NO, I WAS GOING TO,
THEN THEY CANCELED.
SO I'M GONNA TAKE OFF.
- NO.
JUST JOIN US, PLEASE.
narrator: MICHAEL KNEW
HE COULDN'T SAY NO,
BUT HE ALSO KNEW HE COULDN'T
FLIRT IN FRONT OF HER FATHER.
- LET'S DO IT.
narrator: AND AT ANOTHER TABLE,
GOB WAS BEING TAKEN OUT
TO LUNCH.
- READ ME
THE APPETIZERS AGAIN.
- FRIED CHEESE...
WITH CLUB SAUCE.
- [moans]
- POPCORN SHRIMP
WITH CLUB SAUCE.
CHICKEN FINGERS...
- OH, STOP IT.
YOU'RE MAKING ME DIZZY.
- WITH SPICY CLUB SAUCE.
- NO!
I MEAN STOP IT.
- GOB?
- MICHAEL.
- WHY DON'T YOU JOIN US?
- OH, NO.
- I'M JUST HELPING HER EAT.
- OH, IF YOU'D PREFER PRIVACY.
- WHAT? NO.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
I DIDN'T EVEN WANNA HAVE LUNCH
WITH HER IN THE FIRST PLACE.
I JUST--OR--I JU--
[clears throat]
narrator: AND SO LUNCH CONTINUED
WITH BOTH BLUTH BOYS
TRYING TO PROVE
THEY WEREN'T INTERESTED
IN THE WOMEN
THEY WERE INTERESTED IN.
- YOU KNOW, WHEN I SAW THOSE
GOLF CARTS,
IT KIND OF BROUGHT BACK
SOME MEMORIES.
- DID YOU HAVE TOO MUCH
CLUB SAUCE ON YOUR CALAMARI?
- GOB, READ ME THE DESSERTS.
- SHE P-P--
PROBABLY FORGOT
HER OLD LADY GLASSES.
- WHAT IS THE MATTER
WITH YOU, GOBY?
- I'M HAPPY TO READ
TO THE LOVELY LADY.
- "AN ASSORTMENT
OF ICE CREAMS AND SORBETS."
- YOU ALL RIGHT WITH HIM
READING TO YOUR GIRL?
- NOT MY GIRL.
- HUH?
- WHY DON'T YOU READ
TO YOUR GIRL?
- COME ON.
I DON'T HAVE A GIRL.
- NO, THANKS.
ALREADY TAKEN CARE OF.
THANK YOU. THANKS.
- I'M SORRY.
APPARENTLY THERE'S BEEN SOME
INCREASED ACTIVITY ON YOUR CARD.
[whispers]
IT'S BEEN DECLINED.
narrator: IN FACT, THE INCREASED
ACTIVITY ON MICHAEL'S CARD
WAS HIS FATHER.
- DO YOU REALLY THINK THAT
A HOT TUB IS THE BEST THING
FOR SOMEONE WITH YOUR CONDITION?
- I CAN'T SEE, BUT, UH...
I DIDN'T KNOW THERE WAS
A DOCTOR INSTALLING THIS.
- SOMEBODY ORDER A CASE
OF BAG-IN-BOIL FROZEN DINNERS?
- I'M HAPPY TO GET THIS.
NO, NO. NO, PLEASE, STAN.
I'LL DO IT,
UM...
[whispers] CAN YOU PUT THIS
ON MY MOTHER'S CARD?
- YOUR MOTHER?
NO.
NO, NO, NO.
SHE IS A POOL MEMBER ONLY.
AND YOU'LL EXCUSE ME
IF MY TONE IS NOT POLITE,
BUT THIS IS MORE POLITE
THAN SHE HAS EVER TALKED TO ME.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD A FEELING
WHY HIS CREDIT CARD
HAD BEEN REJECTED.
- WHAT THE HELL DID YOU DO?
- [weak howling]
I OVERDID IT.
OH, IT'S SO HOT.
narrator: MICHAEL'S FATHER
HAD JUST INSTALLED A HOT TUB
IN THE ATTIC.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
- I TRIED TO DRINK
SOME OF THE WATER,
AND IT WAS TOO HOT,
AND IT TASTED LIKE SOY SAUCE.
I THINK
THE TERIYAKI CHICKEN BURST.
- THAT'S WHY PEOPLE TYPICALLY
DON'T COOK IN THESE THINGS
OR INSTALL THEM IN ATTICS.
- YOU GOT TO GET IT
OUT OF HERE, MIKEY.
MY EYES,
THEY'RE BURNING.
- WANNA THANK YOU FOR
CHARGING IT TO MY CREDIT CARD.
YOU MADE ME LOOK VERY FOOLISH
IN FRONT OF SALLY SITWELL.
- DID YOU STICK IT TO HER?
- NO, I DIDN'T.
YOU SCREWED THAT UP, JUST LIKE
YOU SCREWED UP THIS HOT TUB.
IS THAT VEAL MARSALA
STUCK IN THE INTAKE?
- THEY ALL LOOK SO GOOD
ON THE BOXES.
YOU KNOW, IT'S GOOD
YOU BACKED OFF SALLY.
I DON'T NEED THAT GUY SAYING
HIS DAUGHTER'S STICKING IT
TO MY LOSER SON.
- YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
THE REASON THAT I NEVER
WENT AFTER HER
IS BECAUSE
YOU'RE ALWAYS PUSHING ME,
BUT NOW THAT I KNOW
THAT I DON'T HAVE YOUR APPROVAL,
I-I THINK THAT, UH...
I THINK THAT I'LL FINALLY
GO FOR IT.
- THIS ISN'T TURNING INTO
THE PARTY HANGOUT I HOPED.
- HEY.
- HEY, DAD, I THOUGHT I HEARD
SOMETHING BEFORE,
LIKE A WOLF DROWNING
OR SOMETHING.
- I THINK THAT THAT WAS
MAYBE THE HOUSE SETTLING.
SPEAKING OF SETTLING, HOW'S ANN?
I MEAN, HAVE YOU--HAVE YOU
SETTLED ON
AN ARTIST'S WORK TO BURN?
- WELL, I WAS THINKING EMINEM
FOR A WHILE.
- SURE.
- BUT, YOU KNOW, EVERYONE IS
GONNA BE BURNING EMINEM.
SO, YOU KNOW--
AND THEN I GOT THIS
PAT BOONE ALBUM,
BUT THE GUY IS CHRISTIAN.
BUT, YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW.
SOMEBODY'S GOT TO BURN, RIGHT?
- WELL, I GUESS.
- ALL RIGHT.
- [sighs]
- HEY.
- OH, BOY, I GOT SOME LOOKS
ON THE BUS 'CAUSE OF THIS.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH THAT THING?
- I AM GOING TO CATCH THAT WOLF,
MICHAEL.
I'M GONNA SHOOT IT
WITH THIS TRANQUILIZER GUN,
GET THE REWARD,
AND BID ON MY WOMAN
AT THE CHARITY AUCTION.
- ISN'T THERE SOME
KIND OF A WAITING PERIOD
FOR A RIFLE LIKE THAT?
- [laughs]
IT TURNS OUT THERE IS.
- TWO WEEKS?
ISN'T THERE A LOOPHOLE?
- THERE IS A GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE.
- AND WHAT TIMING, HUH?
I MEAN, RIGHT OUT BACK
THEY WERE HAVING ONE.
GOB, I'M GOING HUNTING
FOR MY WIFE.
- HOW LAME WAS LUCILLE 2
AT LUNCH, HUH?
- YOU'VE GOTTEN ATTACHED,
HAVEN'T YOU?
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ANYBODY
ABOUT THIS, ARE YOU?
- COME ON.
I'M NOT ONE TO JUDGE.
EVERY TIME I'VE GONE OUT
WITH SALLY,
I'VE LOOKED LIKE
I'M 12 YEARS OLD.
BUT, YES, I PROBABLY WILL
TELL PEOPLE ABOUT THIS.
- MAYBE WE CAN STRIKE UP A DEAL.
YOU KEEP THIS TO YOURSELF,
I HELP YOU GET SALLY.
SIPHON A LITTLE
SOMETHING FROM HER CAR,
YOU SHOW UP IN THE CORVETTE,
LOOKING LIKE A MAN.
CAR TROUBLES?
- PROBABLY SHOULDN'T DO
THE FIREBALL
WHEN YOU SIPHON THE GAS.
- I GUESS THIS FLINT'S STILL GOT
A LITTLE LIFE LEFT IN IT, HUH?
narrator: LINDSAY, MEANWHILE,
WAS WAITING IN THE PARK
FOR HER DATE WITH MOSES TAYLOR.
- SORRY I'M LATE.
FANS.
SOMETIMES IT TAKES A WHILE
TO JAR THEIR MEMORIES.
NICE FUR.
YOU KNOW, THERE ARE SOME NUTS
OUT THERE
WHO'D WANNA THROW RED PAINT
ALL OVER YOU.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I THINK THERE'S ONE
RIGHT OVER THERE.
- OH, MY GOD. YOU'RE--
- SOMEONE NEEDS TO READ THIS.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
LINDSAY'S HEEL WENT OUT.
[grunts]
[howls]
[gunshot]
- I GOT HIM.
- FALSE ALARM.
CRAP.
- I'M BEING SAVED
BY FRANK WRENCH.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT.
- FRANK WRENCH.
- SHUT UP.
narrator: BUT, UNBEKNOWNST
TO LINDSAY AND TOBIAS,
THE ACTOR WHO PLAYED
FRANK WRENCH WASN'T SAVING HER,
BUT WAS JUST TRYING
TO DISTANCE HIMSELF
FROM THE OUTLANDISH "MOSES
TAYLOR HUNTS PEOPLE" SCANDAL
THAT HAD BEEN STARTED
BY A RABID ANTI-GUN FANATIC.
narrator: AND THAT NIGHT,
MICHAEL WENT TO HELP SALLY
WITH THE CAR PROBLEMS
GOB HAD CREATED.
- THE HELL?
narrator: ONLY TO FIND OUT
THINGS HAD GOTTEN
OUT OF HAND FOR GOB.
MICHAEL DID LOOK HEROIC
AS HE WENT TO PUT OUT THE FIRE.
UNFORTUNATELY, SALLY ARRIVED
TOO LATE TO SEE HIM THAT WAY.
- GOD, WHAT HAPPENED?
- CAR TROUBLE?
[coughing]
narrator: GOB HAD JUST
BLOWN UP A CAR.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW,
I'M RUNNING FOR MY LIFE.
AND ALL I COULD THINK WAS,
IF SOMETHING WERE TO
EVER HAPPEN TO ME,
HOW SAD I'D BE, YOU KNOW?
- WHAT YOU DID TO ME
AT LUNCH TODAY,
YOU WERE ASHAMED TO BE
WITH ME.
- NO! I WAS ASHAMED TO BE
SEEN WITH YOU.
I LIKE BEING WITH YOU.
- I'M SORRY,
BUT YOU HAVE NO COURAGE.
- HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT?
SHH.
I THOUGHT I HEARD MY MOM.
[whispers]
HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT?
narrator: AND ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE WALL,
LUCILLE WAS FINALIZING
HER PLANS FOR THE EVENING.
- YOU CAN BID UP TO $10,000.
- THE DEAL IS OFF.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME IT WAS
A RESTRICTED MEMBERSHIP.
FIND SOMEBODY ELSE
TO DO YOUR BIDDING.
- THERE IS NO ONE ELSE.
[coughing]
- HI.
THEY SAID I COULD
SEE YOU FINALLY.
- YES.
- GOD, I JUST FEEL AWFUL
FOR WHOEVER'S CAR THAT WAS.
- MM-HMM.
I KNOW IT.
[coughs]
SALLY, I WAS THINKING
THAT MAYBE YOU AND I COULD--
[coughing]
DON'T TRY TO TALK.
I HAVE TO RUN ANYWAY.
I GOT TO DO THIS
CHARITY AUCTION THING.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
YOUR BLUE CROSS BLUE SHIELD
WAS DENIED.
WE'VE CALLED YOUR MOTHER.
[coughing]
- I'LL BE BACK.
I'LL CHECK ON YOU LATER.
FEEL BETTER.
GO OUT SOMETIME.
[grunts]
narrator: MICHAEL DECIDED
TO BID ON HER AT THE AUCTION,
AND HE KNEW JUST WHERE HE COULD
GET THE MONEY TO DO SO.
- YEAH.
START DRAINING THE HOT TUB.
IT'S GOING BACK.
narrator: AND LUCILLE,
WITH NO OTHER PROSPECTS,
TURNED TO THE SON SHE LEAST
EXPECTED TO SUPPORT HER.
GOB, I DON'T SUPPOSE
I COULD PAY YOU
TO BID ON ME
AT A CHARITY AUCTION.
narrator: AND GOB WAS JUST
DEPRESSED ENOUGH TO DO SO.
- WHATEVER YOU WANT.
- OH, GOODY.
narrator: AND FINALLY,
GEORGE MICHAEL AND ANN'S
CHRISTIAN MUSIC BONFIRE
WAS UNDER WAY.
- WITHOUT EVER GOING TO THE GYM.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE HOW MANY
PEOPLE YOU TOLD ABOUT THIS.
- YEAH, I HOPE I DIDN'T
CONFUSE PEOPLE
BY SAYING IT WAS
A CD BURNING PARTY.
- GREAT PARTY!
MAEBY, I BURNED LIKE 10 CD's
FROM SOMEBODY'S MP3 PLAYER.
- THIS IS A DISASTER.
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE YOU SHOULD
JUST TRY LISTENING
TO SOME OF THE MUSIC.
- YEAH, SOME OF THE ARTISTS
ARE KIND OF TALENTED.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE HEARD OF
THE JERKY BOYS.
THEY DO, LIKE,
THESE PRANK PHONE CALLS.
IT'S KIND OF OLD SCHOOL,
BUT I HAVE THE TAPE IN MY ROOM.
I ACCIDENTALLY
DIDN'T BURN IT YET.
narrator:
MEANWHILE, THE AUCTION BEGAN.
- NEXT UP, WE'VE GOT LAST YEAR'S
CHARITY CASE, LINDSAY FUNKE.
- narrator: LINDSAY SHOWED UP.
- OH, NO.
NOT AGAIN.
narrator: ALTHOUGH SHE WAS
STILL FEELING THE EFFECTS
OF THE TRANQUILIZER.
- HUNDRED DOLLARS, FOLKS?
- STICK A WRENCH IN ME.
I'M DONE.
- ANYBODY GOT 50?
- MY WIFE IS HUMILIATED.
THIS IS MY CHANCE TO RIGHT
THE SMALL WRONG THAT I DID.
- YOU SHOT HER IN THE ASS
WITH ABOUT FOUR OUNCES
OF HORSE TRANQUILIZER.
- I HAVEN'T BEEN
THE PERFECT HUSBAND.
YES, I ADMIT THAT.
BUT NOW IS MY CHANCE
TO BE A HERO.
PLEASE, MICHAEL,
GIVE ME SOME OF YOUR MONEY.
- DOES ANYBODY HAVE 10?
- I'VE GOT $5,000,
AND I NEED THAT FOR SALLY,
BUT IF YOU WANT TO MAKE
A LOW BID--
- $5,000.
- FOR THAT?
SOLD.
- [groans]
I THINK YOU OVERPAID.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL'S
PROSPECTS WERE ALSO IMPROVING
AS THE TWO MADE
PRANK PHONE CALLS TOGETHER.
- LET ME TRY.
HEY, RUBBERNECK.
- ANN, COULD YOU
AND GEORGE MICHAEL
PLEASE CALL SOMEONE ELSE
FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
- HE KNOWS IT WAS US.
- WHAT?
- WE FINALLY GOT
A GOOD ONE COMIN' UP.
SALLY SITWELL.
WHAT DO I HEAR?
- $500.
- YOU'RE NOT BIDDING?
I WAS HOPING YOU WOULD.
- YOU WERE?
- YOU'RE A GOOD KID.
YOU ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
NOT LIKE THAT SHOWBOAT
OF A FATHER OF YOURS,
IF YOU DON'T MIND ME SAYING.
- I'VE CALLED HIM SO MUCH WORSE.
THE TRUTH IS, SIR,
I AM INTERESTED,
BUT I DON'T HAVE THE MONEY
TO BUY YOUR DAUGHTER.
- [chuckles]
WELL, YOU SURE DO DRIVE
A NICE CAR,
AND I NEED ONE.
MINE GOT TORCHED TODAY.
- DROP IT OFF WHEN YOU
DROP MY DAUGHTER OFF TONIGHT.
narrator: AND FINALLY, WITH BOTH
THE APPROVAL OF SALLY'S FATHER
AND THE LACK OF APPROVAL
OF HIS OWN,
MICHAEL WAS READY
TO MAKE HIS MOVE.
- $15,000.
- WHAT?
- WOW.
- YEAH.
- I GOT TO TELL YOU,
THIS PUTS A LOT OF PRESSURE
ON ME.
- IT'S FOR A GOOD CAUSE.
- I HEARD IT WAS
TO RESEED THE GREENS.
GONNA BE A LOT OF SHIFTS FOR YOU
AT THE BANANA STAND, HUH?
- I SHOULD BE HONEST WITH YOU.
I DON'T HAVE THAT MUCH MONEY,
AND I SOLD THE CORVETTE
TO COVER IT.
- THAT WAS QUICK.
TO WHO?
- YOUR FATHER,
AS A MATTER OF FACT.
- MY FATHER?
- YEAH.
- MY FATHER CAN'T DRIVE
A CONVERTIBLE.
- MIND IF I OPEN IT UP?
WOW!
GOT SOME PICKUP.
- THIS IS JUST LIKE HIM.
HE ALWAYS INTERFERES
WITH EVERYONE I DATE.
WELL, YOU CAN TELL HIM
TO GIVE YOU YOUR CAR BACK.
- BUT I BOUGHT YOU.
- I'M SORRY.
I'M NOT LIKE YOU.
I'D ALMOST RATHER DATE SOMEONE
MY FATHER DOESN'T APPROVE OF.
THANKS ANYWAY.
- THAT--THAT--
THAT IS LIKE ME.
THAT'S EXACTLY LIKE ME!
narrator: AND SOON IT WAS TIME
FOR GOB TO BID ON HIS MOTHER.
- NOT ALL BAD.
THE ONLY ONE BIDDING ON
LUCILLE 2
IS THAT HAIRLESS SITWELL.
- SEVEN RIGHT THERE
FROM THAT GENTLEMEN.
- SITWELL'S BIDDING
ON LUCILLE 2?
FIRST HE FIRES ME,
THEN HE STEALS MY...
- GOING ONCE.
- MOTHER'S BEST FRIEND.
- GOING TWICE.
NINE GOING TWICE.
- $10,000.
- OH, HOW GRAND.
- SOLD.
UP FROM $800
TO $10,000.
- WOW, YOU GUYS REALLY WANT
A NEW GOLF COURSE,
AND ALL FROM NONMEMBERS.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
- GEORGE SR. SHOWS UP
TO BID ON LUCILLE.
- [howling]
narrator: BUT THE SOUND
OF HIS WOLF CALL
AND THE SMELL OF
CHICKEN TERIYAKI INTERFERE.
- NO, NO, NO, NO!
NO. OH.
OH.
OH, NO.