male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING,
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH ARRIVED HOME
TO FIND HIS MOTHER, LUCILLE,
IN A STATE OF AGITATION.
- I THINK THE COMPANY'S
IN TROUBLE.
- WHAT TIPPED YOU?
THE FALLING PROFITS,
OR THAT WE'RE A REGULAR FEATURE
ON BILL O'REILLY'S "MOST
RIDICULOUS ITEM OF THE DAY"?
- I'M TALKING ABOUT THE FACT
THAT MY "FRIEND" LUCILLE AUSTERO
BOUGHT OUR COMPANY, AND I THINK
SHE'S GOING FOR A POWER GRAB,
THAT BITCH!
- YOU'RE NOT AT HOME, MOM.
SHE DOESN'T LIVE NEXT DOOR
WHEN YOU'RE HERE.
SECONDLY,
SHE'S ALREADY GRABBED POWER.
SHE'S THE MAJORITY
SHAREHOLDER OF THE COMPANY.
- I'LL TELL YOU WHAT SHE WANTS
TO GRAB: YOUR BROTHER GOB.
narrator: IN FACT, LUCILLE 2
WAS ALREADY WITH GOB--
- YOU LOOK REALLY NICE.
narrator: BUT SHE WAS GROWING
TIRED OF HIS NEEDINESS.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- I'M GOING TO MY SPIN CLASS.
[door closes]
- I THOUGHT YOU HAD VERTIGO.
- SHE'LL SELL THE COMPANY
OR BREAK IT UP INTO
LITTLE PARTS OR SOMETHING,
ALL UNDER THE GUISE OF
"CARING" ABOUT OUR FAMILY.
- GOTTA STOP QUOTING
WHEN YOU DRINK.
I CERTAINLY HOPE
SHE'S NOT PLANNING A MOVE.
- I WOULDN'T PUT IT PAST HER.
SHE'D LOVE TO GET AT ME
ANY WAY SHE COULD.
THAT'S WHY SHE'S BEEN
FLIRTING WITH GOB.
SHE'S TRYING TO PROVE THAT SHE'S
CLOSER TO MY CHILDREN THAN I AM,
BUT THE JOKE'S ON HER,
BECAUSE SHE DOESN'T KNOW
HOW LITTLE I CARE FOR GOB.
- THINK THAT MAKES
THE JOKE ON GOB.
- HEY, DAD.
- HEY, BUDDY.
- WAS THAT GANGY WHO WAS JUST--
- YOU ALL RIGHT? SORRY.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER HAD
A LITTLE ACCIDENT HERE.
- OH, DOES THAT MEAN SHE'S GONNA
HAVE TO COME LIVE WITH US?
- NO, NO. NO. IT WAS--
IT WAS HER DRINK,
AND EVEN IF IT WASN'T, JUST--
DO YOU REMEMBER WHEN I BID
ON SALLY SITWELL
AT THE BACHELORETTE AUCTION?
WELL, THEY SENT ME THIS BASKET
WITH ALL THIS STUFF
FOR OUR DATE, YOU KNOW.
IT'S A WHOLE PACKAGE.
ANYWAY, I THOUGHT THAT MAYBE
WE COULD DO IT TOGETHER,
YOU KNOW, SORT OF LIKE
A VALENTINE'S PRESENT.
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA TAKE SALLY?
- SALLY, NO. NO.
I-I WANTED IT FOR US.
I NEVER WANTED TO BE WITH SALLY.
narrator: ACTUALLY,
MICHAEL HAD GONE OVER
TO SITWELL ENTERPRISES.
- MICHAEL BLUTH TO SEE SALLY.
narrator: ONE DAY EARLIER
TO SET UP A DATE WITH SALLY.
- I'M AFRAID SHE'S NOT HERE,
MICHAEL.
IF YOU'D LIKE ME TO TAKE THE
PACKAGE, I CAN GIVE IT TO HER.
- NO, NO. THIS IS, UH--
THIS IS NOT FOR HER.
IT'S FOR MY SON.
JUST DON'T TELL HER I CAME BY.
narrator:
IN FACT, SALLY WASN'T THERE,
AND THE PERSON MICHAEL SAW
WAS HER FATHER.
- YOU KIDDING? THIS MAKES ME
LOOK LIKE MY DAUGHTER.
- NO ONE'S GOING TO THINK THAT.
- I LOOK LIKE EDGAR WINTER HERE.
FORGET IT.
I GOTTA GET TO SPIN CLASS.
- SO WHAT DO YOU SAY?
WE GOT A BASKETFUL
OF FATHER-SON FUN HERE.
- WHAT'S KAMA SUTRA OIL?
- [clicks tongue]
MAYBE IT'S NOT FOR US.
- AH, VALENTINE'S DAY, WHICH--
OH! WAS YOUR MOTHER HERE?
- HERE. YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'LL HELP YOU UP.
- OH, THAT IS QUITE A BASKET
YOU'VE GOT THERE, MICHAEL.
THAT SALLY SITWELL
IS ONE LUCKY LADY.
- WELL, I'M--I'M NOT SO SURE
THAT SHE'S ACTUALLY...
RIGHT FOR ME, ANYWAY.
BUT YOU GOT ONE OF THESE TOO,
DIDN'T YOU?
YOU BOUGHT LINDSAY
AT THE SAME AUCTION.
- WELL, YES, BUT I'M AFRAID
I PREMATURELY SHOT MY WAD
ON WHAT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
A DRY RUN, IF YOU WILL.
SO NOW I'M AFRAID I HAVE
SOMETHING OF A MESS ON MY HANDS.
- IT'S JUST--THERE'S SO MANY
POORLY CHOSEN WORDS
IN THAT SENTENCE.
narrator:
TOBIAS WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THAT EVERYTHING
WAS PERFECT FOR LINDSAY,
SO HE WENT
TO CHECK IT OUT FIRST.
- OH. BODY CHOCOLATE.
[moans]
IT'S A WONDERFUL PACKAGE.
I'LL TAKE IT.
- YOU JUST DID.
- WHY DON'T YOU TAKE THIS?
I DON'T HAVE ANYONE
TO GO WITH ANYWAY.
- [chuckles]
CAN YOU IMAGINE HOW JEALOUS
THAT WOULD MAKE HER?
[screeching]
"WHERE'S TOBIAS?"
"OH, HE'S JUST SHARING
A ROMANTIC HORSEBACK RIDE
"WITH MICHAEL BLUTH,
AND THEY'RE DIPPING
EACH OTHER IN--"
OH, YOU DIDN'T GET
ANY BODY CHOCOLATE.
- I DIDN'T MEAN WITH ME.
I HATE TO SEE YOU STRUGGLE
LIKE THIS.
IN FACT, WHY DON'T
YOU LET ME ASK HER FOR YOU?
- WELL, MICHAEL, YOU REALLY ARE
QUITE THE CUPID, AREN'T YOU?
I TELL YOU, YOU CAN ZING YOUR
ARROW INTO MY BUTTOCKS ANYTIME.
- OKAY. YOU KNOW WHAT YOU DO?
BUY YOURSELF A TAPE RECORDER.
YOU JUST RECORD YOURSELF
FOR A WHOLE DAY.
I THINK YOU'RE GONNA
BE SURPRISED
AT SOME OF YOUR PHRASING.
- [gasps]
BUTTERSCOTCH! WANT A LICK?
narrator: AND LATER,
LINDSAY STOPPED BY THE OFFICE
AT MICHAEL'S REQUEST.
- GREAT. THANK YOU.
LISTEN.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE MY ROMANCE
PACKAGE AT THE FOUR SEAS HOTEL.
- OH, YAY!
- THAT'S GREAT.
TOBIAS IS GONNA BE THRILLED.
- OH. I HAVE TO GO WITH TOBIAS?
- LINDSAY, YOUR HUSBAND
REALLY WANTS THIS TO WORK.
- COME ON.
LET ME PLAY CUPID THIS YEAR.
- I THOUGHT HE WENT ALREADY.
- I'M GIVING YOU MINE.
- BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID TO ASK
SALLY SITWELL TO GO WITH YOU.
- THAT'S NOT TRUE AT ALL.
- MMM? [imitates chicken]
CHAW-CHEE-CHAW, CHEE-CHAW.
- WHAT IS THAT?
IS THAT A CHICKEN?
- WHAT'S THIS?
- OH. MICHAEL'S SCARED
TO ASK OUT SALLY.
- NO, I'M NOT.
- CHAW-CHEE-CHAW!
- THIS IS PRICELESS.
CAW-CA-CAW! CAW-CA-CAW!
- YOU TOO. THIS IS GREAT.
COME ON.
THESE AREN'T EVEN BIRDS.
I AM NOT--THAT'S ENOUGH.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WORKING.
- LISTEN, I THINK THAT LUCILLE 2
IS UP TO SOMETHING.
- MOM SAID THE SAME THING
WHEN SHE CAME OVER.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS TICKED OFF
'CAUSE YOU'RE SEEING HER.
- WHAT? YOU'RE SEEING LUCILLE 2?
DOES BUSTER KNOW?
- NO. AND I'M NOT.
JUST DON'T TELL PEOPLE.
I'M PLAYING THE PART
OF THE GIGOLO
SO THAT SHE'LL KEEP
THE COMPANY AFLOAT.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT, SOMETHING
WEIRD HAPPENED YESTERDAY
WHEN I WAS TRYING
TO FIND A WAY OUT OF THERE.
[phone ringing]
HELLO?
[dial tone]
narrator: IN FACT, IT WAS
STAN SITWELL CALLING HER,
AS HE'D BECOME QUITE TAKEN
WITH LUCILLE 2 HIMSELF.
- YOU KNOW,
IT ALL MAKES SENSE.
WHY ELSE WOULD SALLY SITWELL
BE AVOIDING ME?
- BECAUSE SHE THINKS
YOU'RE A LOSER.
- AND WHY WOULD LUCILLE 2
BE SO DISTANT TOWARD ME?
- 'CAUSE SHE KNOWS
YOU'RE A LOSER.
- I THINK IT'S PRETTY CLEAR.
LUCILLE 2 AND SITWELL
ARE WORKING ON A BUSINESS DEAL.
LINDSAY, I'D LIKE FOR YOU
TO GO OVER TO SITWELL
AND SEE WHAT YOU CAN FIND OUT.
I CAN'T GO THERE AGAIN.
- WHY DO I HAVE TO DO THAT?
- BECAUSE YOU'VE BEEN
HELPING YOURSELF
TO THE COMPANY MONEY
FOR QUITE SOME TIME.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU DO ANYTHING
FOR THE FAMILY ANYWAY.
- WELL, GOB DOESN'T DO ANYTHING
FOR THE FAMILY.
- HEY, I'M [bleep] LUCILLE 2.
- OH. I COULD DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
- THIS IS WHAT DAD
WAS REALLY GOOD AT--
GETTING US OUT OF TIGHT SPOTS.
narrator: IN FACT,
AT THAT VERY MOMENT,
GEORGE SR. WAS IN A TIGHT SPOT,
AS HE'D GOTTEN HIMSELF
WEDGED UNDER THE FURNACE
WHILE CHASING AFTER
A SOUR BALL
THAT HAD ROLLED OUT
OF HIS POCKET.
- [sighs]
[howls]
narrator:
EVENTUALLY, MICHAEL RESCUED HIM.
- I'M JUST STARTING TO WORRY
SHE'S GONNA SELL US OUT.
- I THINK THE ANSWER
TO THIS PROBLEM IS MONEY.
NOW, THIS MAY JUST BE ME
HAVING MY HEAD
AGAINST A 100-DEGREE
FURNACE FOR AN HOUR,
BUT MAYBE WE SHOULD
BRING IN JACK DORSO.
- UNCLE JACK?
- WELL, NO. HE'S NOT MY UNCLE.
HE'S MY DAD'S FRIEND.
BUT THIS GUY
HAS GOT A FORTUNE.
narrator: JACK DORSO FIRST
ACHIEVED SUCCESS IN THE '40s
AS A COSTAR OF THE RADIO AND
THEN FILM SERIAL,
"RED McGIBBON
AND BULLET: NAZI HUNTERS."
- THERE ARE TWO NAZIS
UP THERE IN THAT DANCE HALL.
- SHOOT ME.
[gunfire]
[glass shatters]
HAPPY VALENTINE'S DAY, NAZIS.
narrator: WHEN THE ACTOR
WHO PLAYED RED McGIBBON
WAS JAILED FOR
HIS COMMUNIST SYMPATHIES,
JACK DORSO MADE ONE ATTEMPT
AT A SOLO BULLET FEATURE.
BUT THE AUDIENCE WAS NOT READY
TO ACCEPT BULLET
AS A ROMANTIC LEAD,
DESPITE HIS POWERFUL UPPER BODY.
SO HE STARTED
A CHAIN OF GYMNASIUMS,
HAVING STOLEN THE IDEA
FROM RED DURING A PRISON VISIT.
AND AS THE YEARS PASSED--
- HEY, JACK!
narrator:
HE BECAME WELL-KNOWN
FOR HIS ANNUAL BIRTHDAY FEATS
OF STRENGTH.
- FIVE POUNDS
FOR EACH YEAR OF MY LIFE.
narrator: SADLY,
HE LOST THE USE OF HIS LEGS
ON HIS 70th BIRTHDAY--
- RELEASE!
narrator: AT THE NEWLY-REMODELED
JACK DORSO'S
IN ALBANY, NEW YORK.
[bones cracking]
- [grunts]
TOO MUCH!
- IF HE'S GOT SO MUCH MONEY, HOW
COME WE NEVER CALLED HIM BEFORE?
- BUT I HAVE.
I MEAN, THERE WOULDN'T BE
A BLUTH COMPANY WITHOUT HIM.
I COULD NEVER HAVE AFFORDED
THAT FIRST TRACT OF LAND.
BUT HE ALWAYS WANTS
SOMETHING IN RETURN.
[sighs]
I DON'T KNOW.
SEE IF YOU CAN TALK YOUR MOTHER
INTO TAKING ANOTHER BULLET
FOR THE BLUTH FAMILY.
narrator: THE FAMILY
GATHERED AT LUCILLE'S
TO WELCOME AND SOLICIT
UNCLE JACK.
AND REMEMBER,
HE WASN'T REALLY THEIR UNCLE.
- BUSTER; NICE OF YOU
TO TAKE A BREAK
FROM THAT COMMON WHORE
YOU'VE BEEN DATING.
- SHE IS NOT A WHORE, MOTHER.
SHE HAPPENS TO BE THE NEW
SECRETARY OF THE BLUTH COMPANY.
AND, YES, SHE'S MORE EXPERIENCED
THAN A NORMAL GIRL.
BUT SOMETIMES LOVE
SHOULD BE TERRIFYING.
narrator:
IN FACT,
BUSTER HAD EVEN STARTED
USING HIS ARMY STEALTH TRAINING.
- BUSTER.
- I'LL BE RIGHT IN, AND THEN
MAYBE WE CAN TALK ABOUT--
[grunts]
MAKIN' THAT LOVE.
[door handle rattling]
- I SHOULDN'T COMPLAIN.
IT'S BETTER THAN YOU DATING
LUCILLE 2, THAT BITCH!
- LUCILLE 2's NOT A "B," MOTHER.
SHE'S KIND, AND SHE'S CARING,
AND SHE'S CERTAINLY
LESS EXPERIENCED THAN
THAT WHORE THAT I'M DATING NOW.
narrator: AND PERHAPS IT WAS
SCREAMING IT OUT LOUD
THAT MADE BUSTER REALIZE
THAT HE MISSED LUCILLE 2.
- I'M WONDERING
IF YOU CAN KEEP
SOME OF THE MORE
PIERCING PROFANITIES DOWN
WHEN THE 90-YEAR-OLD
FITNESS BUFF GETS HERE?
- YOU KNOW, MICHAEL, I WAS HAPPY
TO CALL UNCLE JACK FOR YOU,
BUT THAT'S AS MUCH
AS I'M GOING TO DO.
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
I NEED A MORE VITAL MAN.
[knocking at door]
- SOMEONE ORDER 140 POUNDS
OF UPPER-BODY STRENGTH?
- WELL, HE CERTAINLY
SOUNDS VITAL TO ME.
- WALK, DRAGON! WALK!
ENTER THE ROOM!
- WELCOME, UNCLE JACK.
- HE'S HALF DEAF.
IT WAS A STUPID, STUPID HIRE.
NOT "HIGHER."
EYE LEVEL! EYE LEVEL!
KISSES, AND THEN WE TALK.
WHICH ONE IS MICHAEL?
- UH--
- SWOOP ME!
- OH.
- I, UH, REALLY APPRECIATE
YOU COMING OVER, UNCLE JACK.
- THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
YOU MAY BE AMAZED.
I'M INVITED INTO
VERY FEW PERSONAL HOMES.
TO THE NUTS!
THE BRIDGE MIX!
THE BRIDGE MIX! FOOL!
- HEY, FAKE UNCLE JACK.
- IS THIS THE BOY?
IS THIS THE LITTLE ONE?
MY GOD, YOU'RE AN ARMY MAN.
- WELL--
[chuckles]
- I WAS NEVER IN THE ARMY.
I WAS IN THE PICTURES.
HERE COMES UNCLE JACK.
SHOOT ME!
- [screams]
OH, GOD!
- [gasps]
- [groans]
- LOOK AT THAT. I PINNED HIM.
I PINNED THE ARMY MAN.
GOD BLESS YOU FOR BEING
IN THE ARMY.
UP, DRAGON!
- [whimpering]
- LIFT. LIFT WITH VIGOR.
- REMEMBER ME?
- LUCILLE. YOU LOOK YOUNGER
THAN YOU DID THE DAY I--
- OH, YOU OLD FOOL.
I'M LUCILLE.
- [screams]
YOU LOOK FABULOUS.
BACK TO THE BLONDE.
ISN'T SHE BEAUTIFUL?
OH, YEAH.
[gobbling]
- HE'S KIND OF SCARY,
THAT GUY, HUH?
- NO, NOT TO ME.
I THINK HE'S KIND OF COOL.
- WELL, WHY DON'T YOU GO
GET YOUR KISS
FROM MR. COOL HALF-MAN?
- [scoffs]
I'D BE FINE WITH THAT.
- LET'S GO.
- SO WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
- COME ON.
- WHY, SHE'S NO BIGGER
THAN ONE OF MY LEGS.
SHAKE THEM FOR HER.
[grunting]
- EXCUSE ME, UNCLE JACK.
I'M GEORGE MICHAEL.
- [gurgles]
IT'S OKAY. JUST IGNORE IT!
IGNORE IT.
JUST SOMETHING THE BODY DOES
WHEN YOU'RE SHAKEN.
[gurgles] DON'T SHAKE IT!
DON'T SHAKE IT!
TOWEL!
- NOT THE GOOD ONES!
- IS HE DYING?
WHAT IF HE'S DYING?
- [gurgling]
- BOY, THAT DRAGON'S CUTE, HUH?
[sighs]
- WHAT, THE DEAF GIANT
WHO'S HOLDING OUR FAKE UNCLE?
- HE'S BEEN FLIRTING
WITH ME ALL NIGHT.
I WAS THINKING MAYBE IT WOULD
BE BEST FOR THE FAMILY
IF I WENT ON THAT ROMANCE THING
WITH DRAG INSTEAD OF TOBIAS,
WHICH WOULD BE A DRAG.
[chuckles]
- YEAH, THAT'S JUST THE KIND
OF JOKE DRAG CAN'T HEAR.
NO, YOU'RE GONNA GO WITH TOBIAS
OR NOT AT ALL.
NOW TELL ME WHAT YOU FOUND OUT
AT SITWELL.
- OH. YOU STILL WANT ME
TO DO THAT?
- YOU DIDN'T?
LINDSAY, I GIVE YOU ONE THING
TO DO FOR THE BUSINESS,
AND YOU CAN'T EVEN DO IT.
I MEAN, IF YOU'D TRIED AND
FAILED, I'D UNDERSTAND,
BUT YOU DIDN'T EVEN TRY.
- SO, I DIDN'T EVEN FAIL,
AND I DON'T SEE YOU
GIVING ME CREDIT FOR THAT.
- [sighs]
narrator: MICHAEL KNEW THAT
SINCE LINDSAY LET HIM DOWN,
HE HAD NO CHOICE BUT TO ASK
UNCLE JACK
FOR THE MONEY TO SAVE
HIS COMPANY.
- PRETTY.
- YES.
DO YOU THINK YOU SHOULD BE
PERCHED ON THE EDGE
OF THE BUILDING LIKE THIS?
- OH, DRAGON'S GOT ME.
- DRAGON'S IN THE BATHROOM.
- MAMA!
- COME ON. I GOT YA.
I GOT YA. IT'S OKAY.
- [grunts, whimpers]
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL
LAID OUT HIS DILEMMA.
- I JUST DON'T WANT TO SEE
THE FAMILY COMPANY GET RUINED.
- I WAS HOPING THAT
THIS WAS A SOCIAL VISIT--
- WELL--
- PARTICULARLY WHEN
THAT SISTER OF YOURS
STARTED GIVING ME
THE CUTIE EYE.
[growling]
- SHE DID?
- UNFORTUNATELY
THAT MOOSE WAS HOLDING ME,
SO I COULDN'T MAKE MY MOVE.
OF COURSE I COULDN'T MAKE
THAT MOVE WITHOUT THAT MOOSE,
BUT THAT'S MY CHALLENGE.
I WON'T GO WHEELCHAIR!
TWIRL ME AROUND.
- HEY, HEY. NO.
I GOT YOU. I GOT YOU.
- [chokes]
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
- BUT VALENTINE'S DAY IS HERE,
AND I'M ALONE.
THE MOOSE IS NO ONE.
PERHAPS IF I HAD
A LITTLE...COMPANIONSHIP,
I'D BE A LITTLE
MORE DISPOSED TO WHIP OUT
THAT OLD WALLET OF MINE.
- YOU'RE SAYING IF I WERE
TO SET YOU UP WITH MY SISTER,
YOU WOULD CONSIDER
BAILING US OUT?
- OH, JOY. YEAH.
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS TORN.
THE BUSINESS MEANT THE WORLD
TO HIM, BUT HIS SISTER'S HONO-
- LET'S DO IT.
narrator: UH, MEANT A LOT TOO.
- LET'S GO SHARE THE GOOD NEWS.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD OFFERED
HIS SISTER TO HIS UNCLE JACK
IN EXCHANGE FOR MONEY
TO SAVE THE COMPANY.
REMEMBER,
IT'S NOT THEIR REAL UNCLE.
- HE'S CUTE, ISN'T HE?
- SO CUTE.
- IMAGINE HIM WITHOUT
THAT MUSCLY LITTLE OLD GUY
IN HIS ARMS.
- OH, DRAGON. RIGHT.
WELL, THAT'S WHY
I WAS THINKING
MAYBE YOU SHOULD GO WITH DRAGON
ON THAT ROMANTIC GETAWAY.
- OH.
- NOW, I KNOW HE'S WORKING,
SO UNCLE JACK'S
GONNA HAVE TO GO ALONG.
- OH. WELL, AS LONG AS
HE PROMISES NOT TO SHAKE HIM.
- MMM.
- SO, WHAT DID HE SAY
ABOUT THE MONEY?
- HE SAID HE'D LIKE
TO SLEEP ON IT.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
BUSTER HAD DECIDED
TO PURSUE A NEW GIRLFRIEND:
HIS OLD GIRLFRIEND.
- HEY--BROTHER?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M KEEPING AN EYE
ON THE WOMAN
WHO CONTROLS OUR COMPANY.
- IN HER ROBE AND SLIPPIES?
- GETTING INTO HER HEAD.
I THINK SHE'S PLANNING
ON SELLING
OUR COMPANY TO STAN SITWELL.
BUT I'VE LOST HER TRAIL,
AND I DON'T THINK I HAVE
THE SKILLS TO PICK IT UP.
- SKILLS?
[grunts]
- THESE KIND OF SKILLS?
- NOT REALLY.
BUT IF YOU GIVE ME ONE OF
THOSE OUTFITS,
WE CAN HIDE IN THE BUSHES OR
SOMETHING AND SPY ON THEM.
- I WOULD LIKE TO SEE HER AGAIN.
YOU'VE GOT IT.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL TOLD HIS FATHER
THE GOOD NEWS ABOUT UNCLE JACK.
-YOU ARE PIMPING OUT
YOUR SISTER?
- WELL, YOU WERE PIMPING OUT
MY MOTHER.
- YES, BECAUSE SHE WAS
SLEEPING WITH MY BROTHER,
BUT YOUR SISTER?
- EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE FINE.
NO ONE'S GONNA GET HURT.
NO ONE IS GOING TO GET HURT.
- OH. HEY, MICHAEL.
MY DAD WANTED ME TO THANK YOU
FOR THE ROMANTIC GETAWAY.
DON'T TELL ME WHAT THAT MEANS.
- WHERE IS YOUR DAD?
- HE LEFT,
DRESSED ALL WESTERNY.
YOU COULD LEAVE ME
OUT OF THAT PART TOO.
narrator: AND MICHAEL REALIZED
THAT PERHAPS
SOMEBODY WOULD GET HURT.
- I JUST SCREWED
MY BROTHER-IN-LAW.
- WELL, I'M ALL GROWN UP NOW.
narrator: SO MICHAEL RUSHED
TO THE FOUR SEAS HOTEL
TO KEEP TOBIAS FROM FINDING OT
ABOUT LINDSAY'S DATE.
- MICHAEL, THIS IS JEFF.
HE DOES ALL THE HORSE WORK HERE.
YOU'LL MEET HIM AGAIN
AT THE END.
PLUS, HE GETS YOU YOUR JUICE.
NOT YOUR FIRST JUICE,
BUT THE ONE YOU GET AT THE SPA.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU'VE DONE THIS BEFORE.
- BUT NOT WITH A LOVELY LADY.
JEFF DOUBTS ONE'S COMING
AT ALL, DON'T YOU?
SORRY. SORRY.
- ABOUT THE LOVELY LADY--
- STOP. YOU DROPPED THE BOOT.
DROPPED THE BOOT.
narrator: MICHAEL CAME UP WITH
THE ONLY EVASION
HE COULD THINK OF.
- TOBIAS, THE LOVELY LADY, SHE'S
GONNA BE A LITTLE BIT LATE.
SHE'S DOING SOME WORK.
SHE SAID TO GET STARTED
WITHOUT HER.
SADDLE ME UP, JEFF.
- IT'S GONNA TAKE A FEW MINUTES
TO TACK ANOTHER HORSE.
narrator: SO MICHAEL EMBARKED
ON THE ROMANTIC ADVENTURE
HE'D SPENT SO LAVISHLY FOR.
- WELL, YOU CERTAINLY
DIDN'T HELP WITH MY REPUTATION
AS A LADY'S MAN WITH JEFF.
BUT WE'LL CLEAR ALL THAT UP
IN THE SPA WHEN I GET MY FACIAL.
- HEY, DID YOU EVER GET
THAT TAPE RECORDER?
- [chuckles]
YOU'RE FUNNY.
COME ON, BOY.
HOO-CHA-CHA!
narrator: SOON THE NEXT GROUP
BEGAN THEIR ROMANTIC DATE.
- SO NICE OF YOU
TO COVER THIS, UNCLE JACK.
- MY PLEASURE.
IT'S NICE TO DO SOMETHING
YOU DON'T NEED LEGS FOR.
[yells]
[spits, gurgles]
TOWEL!
narrator: AND LUCILLE 2 SHOWED
UP WITH STAN SITWELL,
WHO DID LOOK A LITTLE
LIKE EDGAR WINTER.
AND ONE BY ONE,
THEY EACH ENJOYED THE ACTIVITIES
OF THEIR ROMANTIC GETAWAYS.
- BODY CHOCOLATE?
- NO.
narrator:
OF COURSE, IN THE SPA,
THE JETS PROVED TOO POWERFUL
FOR UNCLE JACK'S TINY LEGS.
THE SPA PORTION
ALSO PROVED CHALLENGING
TO STAN SITWELL AND LUCILLE 2,
WHO IN TURN
WERE BEING FOLLOWED BY BUSTER
AND GOB.
AND SOON, MICHAEL AND TOBIAS
AWAITED
THEIR MASSAGE THERAPISTS.
- [humming]
- SO, UH, TOBIAS,
I'M AFRAID THAT YOUR WIFE
MIGHT NOT ACTUALLY
END UP HERE WITH YOU.
- YOU KNOW, MICHAEL,
PERHAPS I SHOULD BUY YOU
THAT TAPE RECORDER.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA HOW OFTEN
YOU SAY THE WORD "AFRAID"?
- WELL, I KNOW I USED IT
IN THE JACUZZI.
- AND I APOLOGIZE FOR THAT.
I THOUGHT IT WAS A POOL TOY.
BUT YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE WITH SALLY SITWELL,
BUT YOU WERE AFRAID
TO ASK HER.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU CREATE ISSUES, AND YOU
MAKE UP IMAGINARY PROBLEMS,
LIKE THIS MERGER
I HEAR YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT.
- WELL, UH,
YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT--
- [shouting]
- ABOUT ME BEING AFRAID
OF THE WORD "NO," BUT--
YOU KNOW, THE MERGER'S REAL.
I'M NOT IMAGINING THAT.
- LUCILLE!
MICHAEL.
MICHAEL?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- FOLLOWING LUCILLE 2.
SHE'S WITH SITWELL.
SHE PROBABLY FIGURED
THAT WE'D NEVER TRACK HER.
[chuckles]
BUT WE LOST HER.
EVERYONE PUT ON WHITE ROBES
AND OUTSMARTED US.
- LUCILLE!
LINDSAY?
- [grunts]
- LINDSAY.
- WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
LINDSAY'S HERE? WITH TWO MEN?
- SORT OF ONE AND A HALF.
- TOBIAS.
HEY, TOBIAS!
- LINDSAY, LOOK. I--OH.
LUCILLE 2. I'M SORRY.
AND, MISS,
I DON'T KNOW YOUR NAME.
- TOBIAS?
- LUCILLE? SITWELL?
WHAT'S THIS?
- IT'S OUR ROMANTIC GETAWAY,
MICHAEL.
- ROMANTIC? SO, THEN THE COMPANY
ISN'T BEING TAKEN OVER,
SO LINDSAY DOESN'T HAVE
TO BE WITH UNCLE JACK?
OH, TOBIAS.
WE GOTTA STOP LINDS--TOBIAS?
- HOW'D YOU LIKE TO TAKE
A NAP, BALDY?
- I'LL HANDLE THIS.
- SHE'S MY GIRLFRIEND, PAL.
TAKE HIM DOWN, BUSTER.
- YOUR GIRLFRIEND?
THAT'S WHY YOU WERE
IN HER ROBE AND SLIPPIES.
YOU WEREN'T TRYING
TO GET INTO HER HEAD.
YOU WERE TRYING TO GET INTO
HER... ROBE AND SLIPPIES.
SHE'S MY GIRLFRIEND!
[yells]
[both grunting]
- SO THIS IS
WHO YOU CHOOSE OVER ME?
- [grunts] SHE'S NOT WITH HIM.
SHE'S WITH THE BULLET.
- OH, THANK GOD.
- BUT IF YOU WANT A FIGHT,
YOU GOT IT.
SHOOT ME!
- STOP IT! STOP IT!
LOOK, I WASN'T TRYING
TO SELL YOUR COMPANY,
BUT I AM NOW.
THE HELL WITH ALL OF YOU!
- I'M GONNA TRY AND LOWBALL HER.
- NOT WHILE WE'RE AROUND.
- WE'RE NOT DONE HERE, GOB!
- TOBIAS?
TOBIAS, I'M SORRY.
I SET THIS UP FOR LINDSAY.
LINDSAY, I'M SORRY.
- YOU WERE NOT ON A DATE
WITH DRAGON.
- I KNOW THAT, MICHAEL.
IT WAS PRETTY OBVIOUS WHEN
DRAGON KEPT SWOOPING
UNCLE JACK IN FOR A KISS.
YOU SAID I NEVER DID
ANYTHING FOR THE COMPANY.
I-I JUST THOUGHT I'D TRY.
TOBIAS, I NEVER THOUGHT
YOU'D EVER FIGHT FOR ME.
- I HAD NO IDEA
A 90-YEAR-OLD MAN
COULD CAVE IN MY CHEST CAVITY
LIKE THAT.
- DRAGON, WOULD YOU MIND
CARRYING MY HUSBAND TO THE CAR?
- [bones cracking]
[screaming]
- OH, GOD.
- I LOVE TAKIN' A GUY DOWN!
I THINK I SNAPPED ONE
OF HIS RIBS.
NO. IT'S MY LEG.
I'LL BET THAT WOULD HURT.
- I GUESS THE DEAL'S OFF NOW,
NOW THAT I ACTUALLY
NEED YOU TO HELP US OUT?
- I'LL MAKE YOU A DEAL.
YOU CARRY ME,
AND I'LL CARRY YOU.
- THANKS, UNCLE JACK.
- YEAH, I THINK WE SHOULD
GET TO THE HOSPITAL.
I THINK THIS DUCT TAPE
IS THE ONLY THING
THAT'S KEEPING THE ANKLE ON.
OKAY. AH.
RIGHT AROUND THERE.
OH. I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT
INSIDE ME NOW.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
UNCLE JACK BUYS THE COMPANY,
BUT MAKES SOME CHANGES
OF HIS OWN.
- AND HE'S GONNA
MAKE ME PRESIDENT.
[chuckles]
narrator: TOBIAS LISTENS TO
A DAY'S WORTH OF HIS OWN WORDS
TO SEE WHAT MICHAEL
WAS REFERRING TO.
[tape fast forwarding]
- EVEN IF IT MEANS ME TAKING
A CHUBBY, I WILL SUCK IT UP.
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
OH, I'VE BEEN IN
THE FILM BUSINESS FOR A WHILE,
BUT I JUST CAN'T SEEM
TO GET ONE IN THE CAN.
IT'S OUT OF CONTEXT.
I WOULDN'T MIND KISSING THAT IN
BETWEEN THE CHEEKS, SO TO SPEAK.
narrator: AND HE REALIZES
THERE IS SOMETHING DISTINCT
ABOUT THE WAY HE SPEAKS.
- TOBIAS, YOU BLOWHARD!
[chuckles]