male narrator:
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
narrator: MICHAEL WAS HAVING
BRUNCH WITH SALLY SITWELL.
- I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE
WE GOT IN.
THIS PLACE IS
USUALLY SO PACKED ON SUNDAYS.
narrator: IN ADDITION TO
ITS SUNDAY POPULARITY,
THE BISTRO WAS ALSO FAMOUS
FOR SOMETHING CALLED
THE SKIP'S SCRAMBLE,
AN EGG DISH THAT CONTAINED
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
DON'T ORDER THE SKIP'S SCRAMBLE.
- JUST MORE GOOD LUCK.
EVERYTHING'S BEEN GOING SO WELL
SINCE WE STARTED GOIN' OUT.
I THINK WE'VE ACTUALLY
GONE OUT EIGHT TIMES NOW.
narrator:
WHICH INCLUDED A RECORD-TYING.
THREE LOVEMAKING SESSIONS
IN ONE NIGHT FOR MICHAEL.
- YES!
- JUST THINK HOW DIFFERENT
EVERYTHING IN OUR LIVES WOULD BE
IF WE'D GOTTEN TOGETHER
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
- OF COURSE, I WOULDN'T
HAVE HAD GEORGE MICHAEL.
WE PROBABLY WOULD'VE HAD
AN ENTIRELY DIFFERENT
KIND OF CHILD.
[man singing]
MY LOVE IS A FIRE
- I REALLY HOPE
HE'S OKAY WITH US GOIN' OUT.
WE'RE VERY CLOSE.
WE DON'T KEEP ANYTHING
FROM EACH OTHER.
- OH, NO, IT'S MY DAD.
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE AT WORK.
- YOU KNOW, GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU WORRY TOO MUCH.
IT'S SUNDAY.
YOU'RE ALLOWED TO HAVE
A COUPLE OF HOURS OFF.
YOU DON'T SEE ME NERVOUS
ABOUT BEING
ON MY THIRD VIRGIN MARY.
- WHY WOULD YOU BE NERVOUS?
THERE'S NO ALCOHOL
IN A VIRGIN MARY.
- THERE ISN'T?
THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE.
CAN I GET A VIRGIN PIÑA COLADA
WHEN YOU GET A CHANCE?
NOW WE'LL GET
THINGS STARTED.
- HI. THIS IS SO, UH--
I WAS JUST--
HEY, OKAY.
I WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO SALLY.
- THIS IS GEORGE MICHAEL.
MY NIECE, MAEBY.
- IT'S NICE TO MEET YOU.
- I JUST SHUT DOWN THE
BANANA STAND FOR A HALF AN HOUR.
YOU KNOW, I CAN KEEP IT
OPEN LATE TONIGHT IF YOU--
- NO. NO.
HEY, COME ON.
MAKE ME SOUND
LIKE A TASKMASTER.
BUT IF-- IF YOU WANT TO KEEP IT
OPEN AN EXTRA HOUR.
SO, THIS IS SALLY.
- IS SHE YOUR GIRLFRIEND?
- NO.
YES!
A LITTLE.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA MEET YOU
IN A FEW MINUTES, OKAY?
- OKAY.
- AND MAYBE WE'LL WORK ON
BREAKING THAT RECORD, HUH?
- OKAY.
SHE'S A SHOT-PUTTER.
AND I'M DATING HER.
BUT I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU'RE COMFORTABLE
WITH EVERYTHING.
- WELL, OF COURSE.
WE COULD DOUBLE-DATE.
YOU AND SALLY AND ME AND ANN.
- WHO?
- WHA--ANN.
YES. YES.
- YEAH, WE HAD--
- OF COURSE I KNOW ANN.
YEAH, SEE, I DIDN'T MEAN "WHO?"
I MEANT, UH, "HER?"
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
I LOVE ANN.
- GREAT.
- EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, YOU SAID THAT
YOU COULDN'T COME TO CHURCH
BECAUSE YOU WERE WORKING,
AND NOW YOU'RE DOING NEITHER?
THAT'S QUITE A LOT OF SINS
FOR A SUNDAY AFTERNOON,
DON'T YOU THINK?
- YOUR VIRGIN PIÑA COLADA.
- AND NOW YOU'RE DRINKING?
- NO. WE'RE JUST HAVING
A LITTLE FUN, YOU KNOW.
- I THINK THE CHURCH
AND STUDYING ARE FUN.
I THOUGHT
YOU FELT THE SAME.
- WELL, I DO.
I--I LIKE NOT HAVING FUN.
I LIKE YOUR IDEA OF FUN,
I MEAN.
OUR IDEA OF FUN.
I LIKE NOT HAVING THAT.
- I'M GOING BACK TO CHURCH.
- WELL, SHE JUST KILLED MY BUZZ.
SO, YOU'RE STILL
ENJOYING THIS RELATIONSHIP?
- YOU KNOW, I MEAN, I GUESS
WE'VE LOST SOME OF THE HEAT
SINCE WE HAVE KISSED.
I MEAN,
HOW DO YOU RELIGHT THAT FIRE?
YOU KNOW, BUT I CAN'T
BREAK UP WITH HER.
I ALWAYS JUST ASSUMED
SHE WOULD BREAK UP WITH ME.
- WELL, WE MAY HAVE TO FIND
A WAY TO SPEED THAT PROCESS UP.
narrator: AND LATER THAT DAY,
MICHAEL CAUGHT LINDSAY UP
ON THE EMOTIONAL BOND
HE WAS FORMING WITH SALLY.
- OH, BIG DEAL, THREE TIMES.
I'VE HAD THREE TIMES
PLENTY OF TIMES.
YES!
- DID YOU CALL MY NAME?
- ABSOLUTELY NOT.
- I JUST HOPE THAT
GEORGE MICHAEL
IS REALLY OKAY WITH IT.
- YOU KNOW, I THINK
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR A REASON
THIS ISN'T GOING TO WORK BECAUSE
YOU CAN'T HANDLE HAPPINESS,
AND YOU LIKE TO SUFFER.
- OH, HOW DELICIOUS!
- OH, HEY, LET'S NOT SPIN
IN THE COMFY CHAIR.
- LOOK AT THIS
DELICIOUS PIECE OF IRONY.
I'M BEING SUED FOR DIVORCE.
ME.
- THOUGHT YOU WERE SINGLE?
- YEAH, I KEEP FORGETTING
THAT I GOT MARRIED.
narrator:
GOB MET A WOMAN ONE NIGHT.
AND AFTER
A SERIES OF ESCALATING DARES,
MARRIED HER.
- YES, BUT IT'S ALL
COMING BACK TO ME NOW.
SHE WAS A SEAL DEALER.
SHE RAISED AND SOLD SEALS
TO AQUARIUMS AND MARINE PARKS,
THAT SORT OF THING.
THEN SHE WENT OFF
TO FIGHT HER WAR
AND LEFT ME
TO LOOK AFTER THEM.
narrator:
IT WAS WHILE IN THE SERVICE
THAT HER PENCHANT FOR DARING
FOUND A NATURAL OUTLET.
- I'VE NEVER KNOWN YOU
TO LOOK AFTER A SEAL.
- TURNS OUT
IT'S A MAJOR HASSLE.
TRIED TO INCLUDE ONE
IN MY ACT ONCE.
THERE'S A REASON THAT
YOU DON'T TYPICALLY SEE
LIVE SEALS IN A MAGIC SHOW.
SO WITH A SIMPLE WAVE OF MY--
[barking]
OH, LOOK-IT OVER...THERE.
WELL, ONE OF THE
"DESPERATE HOUSEWIVES,"
LOOKING SO DESPERATE.
[cat screeching]
SO I RELEASED THEM
FROM WHENCE THEY CAME,
AND NOW
SHE'S STOMPING ON MY HEART.
- WHAT'S HER FIRST NAME?
QUICKLY.
- KRINDY.
- NAME'S NOT KRINDY, GOB.
- AH, SAUL ZENTSMAN.
NO, THAT'S HER LAWYER.
WELL, SHE'S GOT A NAME.
AND I'M GONNA
FIND OUT WHAT IT IS,
AND THEN I'M GONNA
MAKE A PUN ON IT,
AND THAT'S
WHAT I'LL CALL HER.
BAD EXAMPLE:
IF HER NAME'S AMY,
I'LL CALL HER BLAMY.
- THAT'S A STRONG DEFENSE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'LL HELP YOU LOOK
FOR BARRY TOMORROW.
I THINK DAD PREPAID HIM
FOR LINDSAY AND TOBIAS'S
DIVORCE ANYWAY.
- LOOK AT US.
THREE RELATIONSHIPS,
ALL FALLING APART.
MAYBE IT'S TIME WE ACTUALLY
TOOK SOME
RESPONSIBILITY FOR THAT.
- I THINK IT'S MOM'S FAULT.
- I WAS GONNA SAY
THE EXACT SAME THING.
- [grinding]
- NO, THAT'S NOT A SPINNER.
- SO THIS IS HOW MY CHILDREN
SPEAK OF ME WHEN I'M NOT HERE.
- WELL, WHAT ARE YOU
DOIN' HERE, MOM?
-  YOUR BROTHER BUSTER
WANTS TO MEET ME
AT THE BEACH TOMORROW.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS ABOUT?
BECAUSE IF IT'S ABOUT
GOING IN THE OCEAN,
THE ANSWER IS NO,
HE'S NOT GOING IN THE OCEAN.
- WELL, THERE ARE
BIGGER DANGERS, MOM.
LIKE, SAY, SIGNING HIM UP
FOR THE ARMY DURING WARTIME.
- WHAT THE HELL
WAS I SUPPOSED TO DO?
MICHAEL MOORE CONFRONTED ME
IN FRONT OF THE WHOLE COUNTRY.
- FIRST OF ALL,
IT WASN'T MICHAEL MOORE.
IT WAS
A MICHAEL MOORE LOOK-ALIKE.
AND IT WASN'T
IN FRONT OF THE WHOLE COUNTRY.
IT WAS FOR A BIT
ON "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE".
- I DON'T KNOW WHO THAT IS,
AND I DON'T CARE TO FIND OUT.
narrator:
BUT THE NEXT DAY,
SHE DID
FIND OUT WHAT BUSTER WANTED.
- OKAY, I THINK WE HAVE ENOUGH
OF YOU TWO KISSING.
- OH, I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU HIRED A PHOTOGRAPHER.
WE HAVEN'T DONE THIS SINCE
THE BALBOA BAY WINDOW MAGAZINE.
- SO, I WANTED YOU TO HAVE
A RECENT PICTURE OF ME,
BECAUSE THEY WANT TO SHIP ME OUT
TOMORROW WITH ARMY.
- WHAT?
TO WHERE?
- IRAQ.
AND I JUST MIGHT BE
OUT OF OPTIONS.
I DON'T WANT TO GO,
BUT THEY KEEP--
- I KNOW WHAT THIS IS ABOUT.
YOU WANT TO GO SWIMMING
IN THE OCEAN.
WELL, YOU CAN FORGET IT.
- I DON'T THINK
THAT'S WHAT THIS IS ABOUT.
- YES, IT IS.
- HE'S TRYING TO PUNISH ME
OR SOMETHING.
WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO "KEEPIN' IT FRESH"?
- I WAS 30 YEARS OLD THEN,
MOTHER.
I'M 32 NOW!
- SHH.
- AND I'M NOT TRYING
TO TEACH YOU A LESSON.
- WELL, I MAY NOT HAVE
BEEN A PERFECT MOTHER.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
KIDS DON'T COME WITH A HANDBOOK.
narrator: IN FACT,
THERE ARE THOUSANDS OF
BOOKS WRITTEN ON CHILD-REARING.
BUT LUCILLE WAS IN DENIAL.
- IF HE WANTS TO GO SWIMMING,
LET HIM.
narrator:
AND BUSTER WAS FAR FROM READY
TO GO SWIMMING IN THE OCEAN.
- [shudders]
narrator: AND LATER,
MICHAEL AND GOB
TRACKED DOWN THEIR ATTORNEY,
BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
-  THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR COMING DOWN HERE.
I'VE GOT A BIG CASE.
I'M REPRESENTING
SKIP CHURCH'S RESTAURANT.
- I DON'T CARE.
- A WAITRESS THAT WORKS THERE
IS CLAIMING
THAT BY EATING SKIP'S SCRAMBLE
SEVERAL TIMES A WEEK
IS MAKING HER A FATTY.
- WE NEED TO SPEAK TO YOU
ABOUT GETTING A DIVORCE FOR GOB.
- OH, WELL, I GOT MICHAEL OUT
OF HIS MARRIAGE, DIDN'T I?
- ACTUALLY, SHE DIED.
- YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
I'VE BEEN TAKING
CREDIT FOR THAT FOR YEARS.
- CREDIT?
- WHO'S THEIR LAWYER?
- SAUL ZENTSMAN.
DO YOU KNOW HIM?
- I HAVE CHINESE WITH HIM
EVERY FRIDAY NIGHT
AT MISS TEMPLE'S.
HE'S TOUGH.
- I JUST WANT MY WIFE BACK.
- HEY, LET'S SAVE IT
FOR THE STAND,
OKAY, TOM JANE?
FINE.
I'LL GET INTO THIS
AS SOON AS I LOSE THIS CASE.
YOU KNOW WHO'S
DEFENDING THE FATTY?
MAGGIE LIZER.
- MAGGIE LIZER,
OUR OLD PROSECUTOR?
narrator: MICHAEL HAD AN AFFAIR
WITH MAGGIE LIZER
WHILE SHE WAS BOTH
PRETENDING TO BE BLIND
AND PROSECUTING THE FAMILY.
IT WAS WITH HER HE'D FIRST SET
THE THREE-TIME RECORD.
- YES!
narrator:
THEIR RELATIONSHIP
ENDED SOMEWHAT ABRUPTLY.
- WOW.
HOW DOES SHE LOOK?
- WELL, SHE'S GET--
IF YOU ASK ME, BIGGER.
narrator: SHE WAS BIGGER--
- ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE
OKAY TO GO ON?
narrator:
BECAUSE SHE WAS PREGNANT.
- IT'S NOT MY BELLY
WE HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT,
YOUR HONOR.
IT'S LORETTA'S.
BEING TEMPTED
DAY IN AND DAY OUT
BY THOSE SKIP'S SCRAMBLES.
BRING 'EM IN, BOYS.
- OH, I'M COOKED.
THEY LOVE HER.
TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I PREFERRED IT
WHEN SHE WAS BLIND.
narrator: AND SO,
MICHAEL CAUGHT UP
WITH HIS ONE-TIME LOVER.
- HOW YOU DOIN'?
WOW, YOU LOOK...FANTASTIC.
- WOW.
HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
SINCE WE HAD AN AFFAIR
AND YOU RUINED MY CAREER.
- YEAH, I WAS GONNA
CALL YOU A COUPLE OF TIMES,
AND THEN I JUST--
I GOT, YOU KNOW,
I GOT TO THINKING, UH,
"WHAT IF SHE BRINGS THAT UP?"
- TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I AM SO RELIEVED NOT TO BE
PRETENDING TO BE BLIND ANYMORE.
IT'S ACTUALLY TAUGHT ME
NOT TO RELY ON CHEAP TRICKS
TO GET THE JURY'S SYMPATHY.
- I'M SORRY, I KNOW
I'M NOT SUPPOSED TO DO THIS,
BUT WE JUST SPEND
SO MUCH TIME IN THAT BOX.
- [gasps]
- I KNITTED YOU SOMETHING.
- OH, JUROR NUMBER FOUR!
GOSH, THANK YOU.
I FEEL SO BAD I FOUGHT SO HARD
TO KEEP YOU OFF THE JURY.
- OH--
- MS. LIZER...
CAN I SEE YOU
IN MY CHAMBERS?
- OH. YES, YOUR HONOR.
narrator: IN FACT,
JUDGE PING
HAD A GIFT FOR MAGGIE TOO--
AN OCEAN-SOUNDS TODDLER ROCKER
HE'D ASKED HIS BAILIFF
TO ASSEMBLE.
- TOO BAD THE TRIAL'S
NOT GOING ANY LONGER.
SHE COULD'VE KNIT YOU
SOMETHING THAT FIT.
- I KNOW.
I'M SO BIG NOW.
- NO, NO, COME ON.
THEY LOOK GREAT.
YOU LOOK GREAT.
YOU LOOK FANTASTIC.
LAST TIME I SAW YOU WAS IN
THAT JURY BOX RIGHT THERE,
WASN'T IT?
WASN'T IT LIKE A YEAR AGO?
- OH, CHIP, YOU KNOW WHAT?
CAN YOU TAKE THIS
BACK TO MY HOUSE?
[strains]
ACTUALLY, IT'S BEEN
ABOUT EIGHT AND A HALF MONTHS.
- EIGHT AND A HALF MONTHS, HUH?
WOW.
I SEE SOMEBODY HAS BEEN
COUNTING THE, UH--
EIGHT AND A HALF MONTHS.
WOW. REALLY?
COULD'VE SWORN IT WAS A YEAR.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD JUST LEARNED...
THAT THE WOMAN
HE'D BEEN INTIMATE WITH
EIGHT AND A HALF MONTHS EARLIER
WAS EIGHT-AND-A-HALF
MONTHS PREGNANT.
- DIDN'T I USE SOMETHING?
- NO. YOU THOUGHT
I WAS BLIND, REMEMBER?
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'RE NOT THE FATHER, MICHAEL.
- [exhales]
- NO PROBLEM.
- REALLY?
- RIGHT.
- YOU SURE?
I MEAN, UH--I COULD BE, THOUGH.
WHAT IF I WAS?
DON'T YOU WANT TO DISCUSS THIS
MAYBE A LITTLE BIT?
- MICHAEL,
I HAVEN'T HEARD FROM YOU.
I--I REALLY DON'T WANT
TO HEAR FROM YOU NOW.
LISTEN, IF YOU'RE INTERESTED,
COME TO THE BAPTISM.
YOU CAN HURL A BIBLE
AT THE BABY.
narrator: AND THAT NIGHT,
MICHAEL MET UP WITH SALLY,
WHERE HE FELT HE NEEDED
TO BE HONEST WITH HER.
- SALLY...
YOU NEED TO KNOW
ABOUT MY CHILD.
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
HE APPROVES.
- NO, THERE MAY BE
ANOTHER CHILD IN THE MIX.
I RAN INTO AN EX.
WE HAD A VERY MESSED UP
RELATIONSHIP.
IT WAS BASED TOTALLY ON LIES.
BUT SHE'S PREGNANT.
SHE SAID SOMETHING
THAT LED ME TO BELIEVE
THAT IT MIGHT BE MINE.
- BUT YOU SAID
SHE WAS A LIAR.
- SH-SHE IS.
SHE SAID IT WASN'T MINE, SO--
- WHY ARE YOU
TELLING ME THIS?
- WELL, BECAUSE OBVIOUSLY
IF IT IS MY CHILD,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
BE RESPONSIBLE FOR IT,
AND THAT'S GONNA MAKE THINGS
AWFULLY COMPLICATED FOR US.
- MICHAEL, YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE ALWAYS LOOKING FOR
THINGS TO GET BETWEEN US.
FIRST, IT WAS,
"WHAT'S YOUR SON GONNA THINK?"
AND NOW YOU THINK
YOU'RE HAVING A BABY,
BECAUSE A WOMAN WHO LIES
TOLD YOU YOU WEREN'T.
- THAT'S A GREAT WAY
TO SAY THAT.
WE REALLY DO COMMUNICATE WELL,
DO YOU KNOW THAT?
- ARE YOU INSANE?
- YOU BROKE UP WITH HER BECAUSE
SOMEBODY WHO DOESN'T WANT YOU
MIGHT BE PREGNANT
WITH YOUR BABY?
- NO, SALLY BROKE UP WITH ME.
AND AS FOR MAGGIE,
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THAT SHE WAS PREGNANT
WHEN I FIRST SAW HER.
ALL I COULD SEE WAS
HER GIANT CHEST--BOX.
SHE HAD THIS--
SOME PEOPLE CALL IT A CHEST.
I CALL IT A BOX.
SHE WAS HOLDING THIS GIANT BOX.
MAYBE I SHOULD'VE
JUST STAYED OUT OF IT.
SHE DID MAKE IT PRETTY CLEAR
THAT SHE DOESN'T WANT ME AROUND.
- COME ON, MICHAEL.
SHE'S PROBABLY
NOT EVEN PREGNANT.
YOU SAID
SHE WAS CARRYING A BIG BOX?
PREGNANT WOMEN
TEND NOT TO DO THAT.
- IT DID SAY "60 POUNDS" ON IT.
OKAY, I-I'VE DONE
THIS WRONG.
I SHOULD'VE FOUND OUT
WHETHER IT WAS A REAL PREGNANCY
BEFORE I TOLD MY DREAM GIRL
ABOUT IT.
- YOU KNOW WHAT I DO, MIKE?
CHECK THEIR URINE.
MAKE 'EM PEE IN A CUP,
AND PEE IN A CUP
RIGHT IN FRONT OF ME.
- YEAH, WELL, THANKS, GOB.
BUT, UH, I THINK WE SHOULD
JUST KEEP ON LOOKIN'.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
I CAN MAKE THAT SOUND LIKE ME.
- SO YOU GET SOMEONE
TO BREAK INTO HER HOUSE,
RIG THE TOILET,
COLLECT THE PEE, TEST IT,
AND EXPOSE THE LIE.
I MEAN, I'D DO IT,
BUT I'M GOIN'
THROUGH A DIVORCE HERE, GUY.
- OH, A PREGNANCY TEST.
[laughs]
THERE'S SOMETHING
WE NEVER HAD, HUH, LINDSAY?
OH, NO.
WE HAD TO CREATE OUR
LITTLE FRANKENSTEIN MONSTER
OUT OF SCIENCE AND MONEY
AND JUST A DASH OF--
MAEBY, WHAT--
H-HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN STANDING THERE?
- I JUST WALKED IN.
- JUST WALKED IN.
[laughs]
SEEMS LIKE ONLY YESTERDAY
YOU WERE BURSTING FORTH
FROM YOUR MOTHER'S FERTILE WOMB.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
TOBIAS AND I WILL BREAK INTO
HER HOUSE AND GET THE SPECIMEN.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR A LITTLE EXCITEMENT.
- YEAH! IT'LL BE FUN.
WE WILL BE
LIKE TRACY AND HEPBURN.
"WHAT DO YOU SAY,
YOU OLD POOP?"
- OH, GOD, HE'S HEPBURN.
- I AM DONE WITH BUSTER.
PUSHES MY BUTTONS.
THAT'S ALL HE DOES.
- HE ALSO ZIPS YOU UP
AND SANDS YOUR ELBOWS.
- NOT ANYMORE. NO, NO, NO.
HE'S PRETENDING
HE'S GOING TO WAR.
MR. BIG SHOT.
GOD KNOWS WHAT
HE'S REALLY DOING.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
HE SAID HE'S GOING TO WAR?
AREN'T YOU WORRIED ABOUT THAT?
- OH, YOU'RE SOUNDING
LIKE YOUR UNCLE.
AND I'VE HAD ENOUGH
OF HIS ATTITUDE TOO.
-THE BOY IS GOING TO WAR.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO FACE THAT.
-IT'S NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS!
- HE IS MY BOY!
I NEED MACAROONS.
- OH, YOU'RE HIGH!
- OH, WELL, YOU CAN WIN
EVERY ARGUMENT LIKE THAT,
BUT THAT DOES NOT
MAKE YOU RIGHT.
- I DON'T WANT YOU TELLING HIM
YOU'RE HIS FATHER!
I NEED ICE!
- CAN'T YOU SEE
YOU'RE IN DENIAL?
- YOU'RE HIGH!
- YOU'RE DRUNK!
- WHERE DID BUSTER
SAY HE WAS GOING?
- IRAQ.
WHICH IS A SHOT AT YOUR FATHER.
THANK GOD
HE'S NOT HERE TO HEAR THIS.
[howling]
- EXCUSE ME ONE SECOND.
IT'S THE PIPES.
- YOU KNOW,
MOTHER LUCILLE,
THERE'S A PSYCHOLOGICAL
CONCEPT KNOWN AS DENIAL
THAT I BELIEVE YOU'RE EVINCING.
IT'S WHEN A THOUGHT
IS SO HATEFUL
THAT THE MIND
LITERALLY REJECTS IT.
- YOU ARE A WORSE PSYCHIATRIST
THAN YOU ARE A SON-IN-LAW,
AND YOU WILL NEVER
GET WORK AS AN ACTOR,
BECAUSE YOU HAVE NO TALENT.
- WELL, IF SHE'S NOT
GOING TO SAY ANYTHING,
I CERTAINLY CAN'T HELP HER.
narrator: AND MAEBY
SAW A WAY TO HELP HER COUSIN.
- I KNOW HOW TO GET RID OF ANN.
YOU PUT HER
IN A ROOM WITH GANGY.
SHE'LL CRITICIZE HER AWAY.
- BUT WHAT WOULD GANGY
HAVE TO CRITICIZE ABOUT ANN?
- OH, GEORGE MICHAEL.
narrator: IN THE ATTIC,
MICHAEL MET WITH GEORGE SR.,
WHO'D OVERHEARD ABOUT BUSTER.
- HE CAN'T GO.
YOU CAN'T LET HIM.
I COMMAND YOU.
- I REALLY HATE IT
WHEN YOU PUT ON THE GOD COSTUME.
narrator: GEORGE SR.
HAD ALWAYS WORN THE GOD COSTUME
AT THE ANNUAL
LIVING CLASSICS PAGEANT,
WHERE HE AND BUSTER
RE-CREATED MICHELANGELO'S
THE CREATION OF ADAM.
- WHAT IF I NEVER GET A CHANCE
TO REACH OUT AND TOUCH
THAT HAND OF HIS AGAIN?
I GOTTA GO TO HIM.
- POP, YOU'RE A WANTED MAN.
YOU CANNOT RISK LEAVING
THE ATTIC ALL THE TIME.
- OH, WHEN?
WHEN HAVE
I EVER LEFT THE ATTIC?
- TWO DAYS AGO. RIGHT?
SAW YOU FLOATING AROUND
THE FORD DEALERSHIP.
- YEAH, WELL, HAVE YOU SEEN
THE NEW FORD MUSTANG?
YOU COULD HUMP THAT HOOD.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
SET THE PLAN IN MOTION
TO GET MAGGIE OUT OF HER HOUSE.
-  HI, MAGGIE.
ARE YOU BLIND AGAIN?
- FOR THE PIZZA GUY.
I GIVE HIM A FIVE.
I TELL HIM TO KEEP THE CHANGE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' HERE,
MICHAEL?
I'M WITH A CLIENT.
- IS THAT THE PIZZA?
- NO! YOU'LL GET YOUR PIZZA.
SHE'S TAKING
THE STAND TOMORROW.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
IT CREAKS.
- THERE'S SO MUCH I DON'T
UNDERSTAND ABOUT THE LAW.
LOOK, MAGGIE,
IF THIS CHILD IS MINE,
I REALLY NEED TO KNOW.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
CAN YOU SPARE A FEW MINUTES
FOR SOMEONE WHO MIGHT BE
THE FATHER OF YOUR BABY?
- OF COURSE I CAN.
- OKAY.
- BUT IT'S NOT YOU.
[knocks at door]
OH, FOR GOD'S SAKES.
- OH, COME ON!
- [scoffs]
FINE.
LET ME GET
MISS FAT ASS OUTTA HERE,
AND I'LL MEET YOU
IN THE CAR.
- OKAY.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF MAGGIE'S HOUSE,
LINDSAY AND TOBIAS WERE
PUTTING THEIR PLAN INTO ACTION.
- I'M CLOAKING MYSELF
IN HER SCENT.
- OH! SHE'S NOT BLIND.
- WELL, SHE WAS
WHEN SHE BOUGHT THIS.
- [laughs]
[footsteps approaching]
OH, MY GOD! THAT'S HER!
- QUICK! GET IN THE TUB!
GET IN THE TUB!
narrator:
BUSTER, MEANWHILE,
RECEIVED AN UNEXPECTED VISITOR.
- I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
IT'S OKAY FOR YOU TO HIDE.
A MAN CAN HIDE.
THERE'S A QUIET COURAGE IN THAT.
- YOU'RE A GOOD UNCLE.
- I'M NOT YOUR UNCLE.
I'M YOUR FATHER.
- WHAT?
- SHH. SHH.
QUIET COURAGE.
HIDE.
narrator:
BUT BUSTER WAS CONFUSED.
- YOU LIED TO ME.
UNCLE OSCAR'S MY FATHER.
HE JUST TOLD ME SO.
AND MAYBE YOU'RE NOT
EVEN MY REAL MOTHER.
FOR ALL I KNOW, LUCILLE 2
IS MY REAL MOTHER.
OH, GOD!
- BUSTER, YOU WERE
NEVER SUPPOSED TO KNOW.
- OH, YEAH?
WELL, HERE'S
SOMETHING YOU SHOULD KNOW.
I'M GOING TO WAR!
narrator:
BUSTER HAD JUST DISCOVERED
HE'D BEEN LIED TO
BY HIS PARENTS.
- I'M GOING TO WAR!
- YOU TOLD HIM
YOU WERE HIS FATHER!
- I DID NO SUCH THING!
- YOU'RE HIGH!
- YOU'RE DRUNK!
- [gasps]
GEORGE.
HE MUST'VE COME HERE
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO BUSTER.
narrator:
AND THAT'S WHEN LUCILLE
SNAPPED OUT OF HER DENIAL.
- MY BABY'S GOING TO WAR.
narrator:
LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
WERE GATHERING EVIDENCE THAT
MAGGIE WAS TRULY PREGNANT.
AND THEY WERE
HAVING FUN DOING IT.
- THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
WE WERE IN THE SHOWER
SINCE OUR HONEYMOON.
- AND THIS TIME, NO TEARS.
- TOBIAS, THIS IS THE BOX THAT
MICHAEL WAS TALKING ABOUT.
"60 POUNDS."
narrator:
BUT IT DIDN'T WEIGH 60 POUNDS.
- [scoffs]
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS STALLING MAGGIE,
AND THEY WERE ALSO HAVING FUN.
- SALLY SITWELL?
YOU KNOW, I THINK I HAD
HER LITTLE PLAY OVEN.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
IT'S A FUNNY NAME.
BUT SHE'S A DOLL.
- YEAH, I HAD ONE.
[phone ringing]
IF YOU PULL HER HAIR,
SHE'D CRY OR SOMETHING.
- THIS ONE KINDA
DOES THAT TOO.
HELLO.
- WE GOT THE PEE,
AND WE'RE GONNA GET IT CHECKED.
BUT, LISTEN,
YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT THAT BOX
THAT SAYS "60 POUNDS,"
IT'S ACTUALLY
LIKE TWO POUNDS.
I THINK SHE'S PREGNANT,
MICHAEL.
I MEAN, THERE'S
BABY STUFF HERE AND--
[laughs]
TOBIAS, STOP IT.
THAT'S FOR THE BABY.
IT'S NOT--OH.
WE'RE HAVING
A REALLY GOOD TIME.
- YEAH?
WELL, I KIND OF AM TOO.
- BYE.
- SO, NO MORE LIES.
TELL ME THE TRUTH.
IF--IF THAT BABY IS MINE,
MAYBE WE'RE MEANT
TO BE TOGETHER.
- OF COURSE IT IS,
MICHAEL.
narrator:
BUT THAT'S WHEN
THE FUNKES DISCOVERED
WHAT WAS IN THE BOX
THAT WAS SO EASY TO LIFT.
- THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
- OKAY, THE BOX WAS LIGHT 'CAUSE
IT HAD A FAKE STOMACH IN IT.
SO IT LOOKS LIKE
SHE'S FAKING IT.
OH, GOD. I HOPE YOU GET THIS.
- WAIT UP, PLEASE.
narrator:
AND GEORGE MICHAEL AND MAEBY
BROUGHT ANN TO THE PENTHOUSE,
IN HOPES THAT
LUCILLE WOULD DRIVE HER AWAY.
- ISN'T ANN GREAT?
- OH, SHE'S LOVELY.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
SHE WAS DISTRACTED BY
THE THOUGHT OF LOSING BUSTER.
- HEY, DO YOU HAVE
ANY BREAD PUDDING?
'CAUSE YOU'D BE SURPRISED
HOW MUCH THIS ONE CAN PUT AWAY.
- HA!
- NOW THAT BUSTER'S NOT HERE,
THERE'S NO ONE TO FINISH IT.
I DON'T CARE
IF I EVER EAT AGAIN.
- YOU KNOW,
WHEN TIMES ARE TOUGH,
YOU CAN ALWAYS TURN TO
THE POWER OF PRAYER.
- HERE WE GO.
- SHOW ME.
- [gasps]
narrator:
THIS WAS A BIG GET FOR GOD.
AND MICHAEL BROUGHT
MAGGIE HOME TO MEET HIS SON.
- THIS IS GONNA BE EASY.
HE'S BEEN SIGNING OFF
ON EVERYONE LATELY.
MAYBE HE CALLED.
[Lindsay's recorded voice]
- HEY, SO WHAT'S
THE DEAL ON ZUCKERKORN?
'CAUSE YOU KNOW MY FAT CASE--
IT'S REALLY PRETTY THIN.
- LYING, UNTRUSTWORTHY--
- YEAH.
PLUS, I HEARD
HE HANGS OUT AT REST STOPS.
- NO, NO.
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT YOU, MAGGIE.
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M SURPRISED.
I SHOULDN'T BE.
YOU'RE A LIAR. YOU LIE.
WELL, I MEAN,
I HEARD HE HANGS OUT
AT REST STOPS. OKAY--
- AND I KEEP BUYING IT TOO.
AND SO MAYBE THERE IS
SOMETHING WRONG WITH ME.
I REALLY THOUGHT WE WERE
STARTIN' TO TRUST EACH OTHER.
AND I JUST GOT
A MESSAGE FROM MY SISTER
SAYING THERE'S A BOX AT YOUR
HOUSE WITH A FAT SUIT IN IT.
WHAT'VE YOU GOT?
LIKE A DIFFERENT
ONE FOR EACH TRIMESTER?
- YOU HAD YOUR SISTER
BREAK INTO MY HOUSE?
- WHICH ONE ARE YOU
WEARIN' RIGHT NOW?
IS THIS
THE READY-TO-BURST MODEL?
NOW, THERE'S ZERO TRUST HERE.
GOOD-BYE.
IT'S BEEN FUN...
NOT.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD HOPED SOMETHING
MORE DRAMATIC WOULD HAVE
COME OUT OF HIS MOUTH.
OR AT LEAST MORE CURRENT.
- OH, YOU'RE SO RIGHT, MICHAEL.
I REALLY CAN'T BE TRUSTED.
'CAUSE I'M FAKIN' IT...
NOT.
- HELLO, MICHAEL.
WELL, MY WIFE AND I
FINALLY HAD THE THRILL
OF SEEING A PLUS SIGN
ON A PREGNANCY TEST.
- YOU'RE GONNA BE A DADDY!
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
BARRY GETS A BIG BREAK
ON HIS CASE.
- THE FAT GIRL
IN MY SKIP CHURCH'S CASE?
NOT FAT.
THE ATTORNEY BOUGHT
HER A FAT SUIT.
OH! I'VE GOT ANOTHER CASE.
MAGGIE IS SUING YOU
FOR PATERNITY.
narrator:
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME,
LUCILLE PRAYS.
- TAKE SOMETHING ELSE FROM US.
DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO
TO KEEP MY BOY
FROM GOING TO WAR.
narrator:
AND BUSTER IS ON HIS WAY...
WHEN HE DECIDES TO PURSUE
A LONG-DELAYED RITE OF PASSAGE.
- LOOSE SEAL!
WATCH OUT FOR LOOSE SEAL!
- I DON'T CARE ABOUT LUCILLE!
SHE LIES!
narrator: AND THEN
A SEAL BITES OFF HIS HAND.
- AAAA!
- ...MEN.