male narrator: NOW THE STORY OF
A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
- GEORGE MICHAEL?
narrator: MICHAEL WAS LOOKING
FOR HIS SON,
WITH WHOM HE HAD
A SECRET TO SHARE.
- THERE YOU ARE. HEY, PAL.
YOU ALONE?
- ALMOST ALWAYS, YEAH.
YOU KNOW, MAEBY'S
NEVER AROUND ANYMORE,
AND ANN'S OFF WITH HER
RELIGIOUS GROUP,
TRYING TO GET "NIP/TUCK"
TAKEN OFF THE AIR.
- THEY DON'T LIKE "NIP/TUCK"?
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
THEY DON'T LIKE ANYTHING.
SOMETHING ABOUT GOD WANTS PEOPLE
TO AGE NATURALLY.
I DON'T KNOW.
IRONICALLY, SHE LIKES GANGY.
- LISTEN, YOU KNOW,
I WOULD NEVER DATE ANYONE
WITHOUT YOU
BEING OKAY WITH IT, RIGHT?
- YEAH,
AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
- GREAT, BECAUSE I DIDN'T
DO IT THIS TIME.
I KIND OF RECONNECTED
WITH THAT BLIND PROSECUTOR
I USED TO DATE, MAGGIE LIZER.
- HER?
DIDN'T SHE TURN OUT
TO NOT BE BLIND THOUGH?
- EXACTLY.
BUT SHE'S FILLED OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
narrator: MICHAEL HADN'T SEEN
HER IN 8 1/2 MONTHS,
DURING WHICH
SHE HAD FILLED OUT.
- REALLY?
COULD HAVE SWORN IT WAS A YEAR.
AND IT SEEMS
AS IF I'M THE FATHER.
- DO YOU KNOW THIS FOR SURE?
I MEAN, SHE DOES LIE.
SHE MIGHT NOT
REALLY BE PREGNANT.
- SEE, THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
BOY, YOU REALLY ARE MY KID.
- GOOD.
- APPARENTLY,
SO IS THIS ONE.
narrator: MICHAEL FOUND THIS OUT
AFTER HAVING LINDSAY
AND TOBIAS
BREAK INTO MAGGIE'S HOUSE
AND HIDE IN THE BATHROOM
TO COLLECT AND TEST
HER URINE.
IT WAS THERE THAT THEY
STUMBLED UPON A FAT SUIT.
- THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
narrator: MICHAEL CONFRONTED
MAGGIE ABOUT THIS.
- OH, YOU'RE SO RIGHT, MICHAEL,
'CAUSE I'M FAKIN' IT.
narrator:
BUT HE WAS PROVEN WRONG.
- NOT.
- MAYBE IT'LL BE EXCITING,
YOU KNOW?
BE A BIG BROTHER. IT'LL BE FUN.
- THERE YOU GO.
IT WOULD BE FUN, WOULDN'T IT?
- BIG BROTHER. ME.
- NOT GONNA HAPPEN THOUGH,
BECAUSE SHE DOESN'T WANT
ANYTHING TO DO WITH ME.
BUT, LOOK,
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN BORED.
YOU AND I ARE GONNA HAVE
SOME FUN TOGETHER.
MAYBE WE'LL EVEN HAVE
OURSELVES A LITTLE ADVENTURE.
- YEAH.
- MEANWHILE, I GUESS THIS
FAMILY'S BIG ENOUGH, HUH?
narrator: IN FACT,
MICHAEL'S FAMILY
HAD JUST GOTTEN
A LITTLE SMALLER.
- HELLO?
- [screaming]
- MOM, YOU'VE GOT TO STOP
STARTING CONVERSATIONS
LIKE THAT.
- SOMETHING HAPPENED TO BUSTER.
HE LOST PART OF HIS BODY.
I DON'T KNOW WHICH ONE.
- THE HAND.
- I TOLD HIM TO STAY OUT OF
THE OCEAN, BUT WE HAD A FIGHT.
WHO REMEMBERS ABOUT WHAT?
narrator: I DO.
BUSTER HAD DISCOVERED THAT HIS
UNCLE OSCAR WAS HIS TRUE FATHER.
- YOU LIED TO ME.
- YOU WERE NEVER SUPPOSED
TO KNOW.
- I'M GOING TO WAR!
narrator: AS AN ACT
OF DEFIANCE TO LUCILLE,
HE FIRST WENT SWIMMING
IN THE OCEAN,
WHERE HE WAS ATTACKED
BY A LOOSE SEAL.
[seal barking]
- IF ONLY
YOUR FATHER WAS HERE.
OH, THAT GEORGE.
GOD ONLY KNOWS WHERE HE IS.
- THE CAR!
- UP YOURS, GRANNY!
- YOU COULDN'T HANDLE IT!
narrator: IN FACT, GEORGE SR.
HAD SNUCK OUT OF THE ATTIC
AND GONE TO A LOCAL
FORD DEALERSHIP.
- YEAH, THE BRONCO'S
BEEN DISCONTINUED.
WE'RE TRYING TO SHED THAT WHOLE
"FUGITIVE ON THE RUN" THING.
THIS IS THE ESCAPE.
- WHAT A FUN NAME, HMM?
- MM-HMM.
- MAY I TEST-DRIVE?
[tires screeching]
[horn honks]
UP YOURS, GRANNY!
- YOU COULDN'T HANDLE IT!
narrator: SOON, MICHAEL
AND GEORGE MICHAEL
ARRIVED AT THE HOSPITAL.
- IF SOMETHING HAPPENS
TO BUSTER, I'LL BE LOST.
- YEAH. EXCUSE ME.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO BE
THE BABY OF THE FAMILY.
- UM, MAEBY'S YOUNGER THAN ME.
- YOU'RE NEVER GOING
IN THE OCEAN!
NEVER!
- WE'RE HERE TO SEE HIM.
- YOU'RE MY BABY!
I'M NEVER LETTING YOU GO!
- PLEASE STAY AWAY FROM MY SON.
- YOU'RE MY BABY NOW!
NO, HE'S MY BABY!
THE HELL WITH ALL OF YOU.
I HAVE A MAN.
[gasps]
- EXCUSE ME.
ARE YOU THE BLUTHS?
- NOT DR. WORDSMITH.
HOW'S MY SON?
HE'S GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
- THANK GOD.
- FINALLY SOME
GOOD NEWS FROM THIS GUY.
- NO OTHER WAY TO TAKE THAT.
- THAT'S A GREAT ATTITUDE.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
IF I WAS GIVEN THIS NEWS,
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I'D TAKE IT THIS WELL.
- BUT YOU SAID
HE WAS ALL RIGHT.
- YES, HE'S LOST HIS LEFT HAND,
SO HE'S GOING TO BE "ALL RIGHT."
- YOU SON OF A BITCH!
I HATE THIS DOCTOR!
- HE'S A VERY LITERAL MAN.
- YES, THAT'S MORE THE WAY
I WOULD TAKE THE NEWS.
- ACTUALLY, I'M RELIEVED.
I DON'T HAVE TO GO TO ARMY
BECAUSE THE SEAL
WITH THE BOW TIE ATTACKED ME.
I FEEL LIKE
I'VE LOST THREE POUNDS.
- SEAL WITH THE BOW TIE?
- YEAH, I THINK THAT'S WHAT
I SAW BITE ME.
NOW I JUST WISH I COULD REMEMBER
WHY I WENT IN THE OCEAN.
DID WE FIGHT OR SOMETHING?
- OF COURSE NOT.
ALTHOUGH I ALWAYS HAVE
WARNED YOU AGAINST THE OCEAN.
SO HAS YOUR FATHER.
- MY FATHER.
[dramatic piano music]
- GEORGE SR.
YOU NEED MORE JUICE.
WHERE'S THE JUICE?
GIVE MY SON THE JUICE!
- BUSTER, IT'S OKAY.
DOCTOR SAYS
YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
AND IF THEY CAN FIND THE HAND,
THEY'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO REATTACH IT.
YOU KNOW, LIKE A TRANSPLANT.
- I'M FINE.
THIS IS A BLESSING.
AND SPEAKING OF BLESSINGS,
I HEARD THERE'S GONNA BE A BABY.
[giggling]
- OH, YEAH, YEAH.
BUT DON'T--PLEASE, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT THAT.
WHAT'S MORE IMPORTANT
IS THAT YOU'RE REALLY DOIN' WELL
WITH THIS, PAL.
MY HAT IS OFF TO YOU.
- AND MY HAND IS OFF TO YOU.
[hysterical laughing]
- [forced laughing]
NO, NO, I MEANT, DON'T GET
YOUR HOPES UP ABOUT THAT--
- HAND TRANSPLANT.
- [forced laugh]
NO, THE, UH, BABY.
THE MOTHER DOESN'T
WANT ME AROUND.
WE KIND OF HAD
A LITTLE BIT OF A FIGHT.
- YOU OBVIOUSLY CARE ABOUT
THIS MAGGIE WOMAN, DON'T YOU?
- YES, I DO. OF COURSE I DO.
- I MEAN, A SEAL DIDN'T BITE
YOUR LINUS OFF, DID IT?
- NO, A SEAL DIDN'T BITE
MY LINUS OFF.
- GOOD. THEN GO TO HER.
ASK FOR HER HAND.
- YEAH.
AND, UH, MAYBE...
I'LL GET ONE FOR MY BROTHER
WHILE I'M AT IT.
- YEAH. GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
- [laughing]
HMM?
GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
GET THE [bleep]
OUT OF MY ROOM!
- OH, MY GOD! BUSTER!
OH, MY GOD!
BUSTER, WHAT'S WRONG? NURSE!
- [screaming]
narrator:
SO AT HIS BROTHER'S SUGGESTION,
MICHAEL WENT TO THE COURTHOUSE
DETERMINED TO WIN MAGGIE BACK.
- HAVE YOU SEEN MAGGIE?
IT'S KIND OF IMPORTANT.
- OH, YOU JUST MISSED HER.
SHE'S IN THE BAR.
WHAT A SPANKING I GAVE HER
IN COURT TODAY.
GO GET 'EM.
- HE SPANKED ME!
- DID YOU SPANK HER?
- NO!
YOU KNOW, THAT WAITRESS
SHE'S REPRESENTING
IS SUING MY CLIENT
FOR MAKING HER FAT.
BUT HERE'S THE THING.
LORETTA IS NOT FAT.
MAGGIE BOUGHT HER A FAT SUIT,
AND I'VE GOT THE RECEIPT
TO PROVE IT.
- OF COURSE.
THAT'S WHAT THE FAT SUIT IS FOR.
WELL, I'VE GOTTA FIND HER.
I OWE HER AN APOLOGY.
YOU SAID SHE'S AT A BAR?
- FRIDAY NIGHT.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TRY
MISS TEMPLE'S.
TELL HER BARRY SAID--[spanks]
OOH, I DID GOOD TODAY.
narrator: AND MICHAEL CAUGHT UP
WITH MAGGIE.
- YOU KNOW,
THERE HAVE BEEN LIES, YES.
BUT IT'S NOT LIKE EITHER ONE
OF US WOULD EVER DO ANYTHING
TO HURT THE OTHER PERSON.
HELLO, OFFICERS.
- WELL, THERE'S NO FURTHER SIGN
OF A BREAK-IN AT YOUR HOUSE.
AND SINCE YOU HAVEN'T CALLED
US BACK,
WE AGAIN LEFT THE NUMBER
IN CASE THERE'S A PROBLEM.
- THANKS, OFFICER TAYLOR.
- JUST NEXT TIME,
UH, CALL US BACK.
- HEY, THE BREAK-IN?
I TOLD YOU THAT WAS US.
- WELL, MAYBE I DID WANT TO
HURT YOU, BECAUSE I WAS HURT.
I MEAN, THE ONLY REASON
YOU'RE HERE
IS OUT OF LOYALTY TO THE BABY.
- IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT THE BABY.
MAGGIE, THERE WAS A REASON
THAT YOU AND I
GOT TOGETHER
IN THE FIRST PLACE
WHEN WE MADE THIS BABY,
OKAY?
THERE'S SOMETHING HERE,
AS LONG AS WE NEVER LIE
TO EACH OTHER AGAIN.
- WELL, THEN I HAVE TO
COME CLEAN ABOUT ONE MORE THING.
- OH, NO.
- YOU'RE NOT THE FATHER.
- COME ON.
- I WENT TO A SPERM BANK, OKAY,
THE WEEK BEFORE WE EVEN MET.
THE FATHER'S SOME GUY
FROM HARVARD,
BUT THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
- THAT'S GREAT.
HE'S PROBABLY SOME GEEK
"SIMPSONS" WRITER'S KID.
- I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D MEET SOMEONE LIKE YOU.
- MMM.
- BUT COME ON.
I MEAN, DO YOU STILL
REALLY WANT ME?
ARE YOU REALLY
THAT GREAT OF A GUY?
narrator: MICHAEL HAD ALWAYS
THOUGHT OF HIMSELF
AS THAT GREAT A GUY.
THE KIND OF GUY WHO COULD
RAISE SOMEONE ELSE'S BABY.
- OF COURSE I AM.
narrator:
BUT HE WASN'T,
AND HE REGRETTED IT
THE MOMENT HE SAID IT.
[mouthing words]
THE NEXT DAY,
THE FAMILY GATHERED
TO WELCOME BUSTER HOME
FROM THE HOSPITAL.
- HE'S COMING.
WHAT HE'S WEARING IS TEMPORARY.
PLEASE DON'T COMMENT ON IT
OR SALUTE HIM
LIKE THAT IDIOT GUARD
DOWN THERE DID TO HIM.
- WELL, LOOK WHO'S BACK.
LET'S ALL SAY HELLO.
- HI.
- AND WHILE YOU'RE AT IT,
LET'S ALL GIVE ME A BIG HAND!
[forced laughter]
- GEORGE MICHAEL, GET YOUR UNCLE
A BANDAGE FOR HIS FOREHEAD.
- AND WHILE YOU'RE AT IT,
UH, GET TWO.
- OH, MY GOD!
- GUESS THIS MEANS
YOU DON'T WANNA
PLAY "GOT YOUR NOSE" WITH ME.
- [forced laughing]
- OH, WHAT'S THE MATTER,
BUSTER?
DID YOU HURT YOURSELF?
- UH, HI, GOB.
- OH, MY GOD!
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR--
HE'S GOT NO HAND!
- BUSTER WENT SWIMMING
IN THE OCEAN,
AND, ACCORDING TO HIM, A SEAL
WITH A BOW TIE BIT OFF HIS HAND.
- BOW TIE?
- IT'S MERELY THE PLAYFUL
MUTTERINGS OF THE SHOCK VICTIM.
A SEAL WOULD NEVER PREY
ON A HUMAN,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
IT HAD ACQUIRED A TASTE
FOR MAMMAL BLOOD.
narrator: GOB HAD RECENTLY
DRESSED A SEAL IN A BOW TIE
AND USED HIM IN A MAGIC TRICK.
WHEN IT FAILED, HE RELEASED
THE SEAL INTO THE OCEAN.
[cat screeches]
- YOU'RE BACK IN THE REAL WORLD.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BE HAND-FED ANYMORE.
HOW THE HELL WOULD A SEAL KNOW
HOW TO TIE A BOW TIE ANYWAY?
I CAN BARELY TIE THE YELLOW
ONE THAT I WEAR IN MY ACT.
- THIS ONE HAD A YELLOW BOW TIE!
- REALLY?
narrator: AND LATER,
LUCILLE COULD NOT CONTAIN
HER GUILT ANY LONGER.
- I DID THIS.
I PRAYED THAT GOD TAKE ANYTHING
HE WANTED FROM US
SO THAT BUSTER WOULDN'T
HAVE TO GO TO WAR.
- OH, MOM,
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS,
GOD'S NOT GONNA TAKE
A CALL FROM YOU.
- I DID THIS.
I THINK THAT THE SEAL
WITH THE YELLOW BOW TIE
MIGHT BE THE ONE
THAT I RELEASED INTO THE SEA
AFTER GIVING IT
THE TASTE FOR MAMMAL BLOOD.
- OKAY, YOU'VE GOT A BETTER CASE
THAN MOM DOES.
- STILL, I COULD
HUNT DOWN THAT SEAL.
- WELL, THEY SAID IF YOU
RETRIEVE BUSTER'S HAND,
THEY MIGHT BE ABLE
TO DO A TRANSPLANT.
- AT THE VERY LEAST,
I CAN REMOVE
THAT INCRIMINATING BOW TIE.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
TOLD LINDSAY
ABOUT HIS COMMITMENT
TO MAGGIE
AND THE CHILD THAT WASN'T HIS.
- WELL, FIRST OF ALL,
I'M SURE THERE ARE WRITERS
ON "THE SIMPSONS"
WHO AREN'T GEEKS.
AND SECONDLY,
I THINK THIS COMMITMENT
YOU'RE MAKING IS GREAT.
- IT IS.
IT'S GREAT. IT'S GREAT.
I DO THINK SOMETHING
MIGHT BE UP, THOUGH.
WHAT IF SHE'S STILL LYING?
- OH, NO, YOU'RE TRYING
TO GET OUT OF THIS, AREN'T YOU?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A GOOD GUY.
- I AM A GOOD GUY.
- IS HE TRYING TO GET OUT
OF HAVING THIS BABY?
- WE WANT THIS CHILD.
IT'S GIVEN US A REASON
TO STAY TOGETHER.
narrator: IN FACT, IT WAS
INVESTIGATING THE PREGNANCY
THAT HAD REIGNITED
LINDSAY AND TOBIAS'S PASSION.
IT WAS WEIRD.
- WHERE'S YOUR CHILD?
- I DON'T HAVE A CHILD, MICHAEL.
- WE DON'T HAVE A CHILD,
MICHAEL.
- THAT'S WHY WE WANT--
both: OH.
- DID YOU MEAN MAEBY?
- I DID MEAN MAEBY.
- WELL, SHE'S HARDLY A CHILD,
IS SHE, MICHAEL?
- YEAH.
AND WE KNOW WHERE SHE IS.
SHE'S WITH HER DEBATE CLUB,
AND THEY'RE ON THEIR WAY TO
SACREMENDE FOR THE SEMIFINALS.
narrator:
SHE WASN'T.
AND A GOOGLE SEARCH
OF THE WORD "SACREMENDE"
ONLY CAME UP WITH THIS.
IN FACT,
SHE WAS OVERSEEING A REMAKE
OF "THE OLD MAN AND THE SEA"
FOR THE FILM STUDIO WHERE SHE'D
BLUFFED HER WAY INTO A JOB.
- WHAT ON EARTH
IS TAKING SO LONG?
AM I THE ONLY ONE WHO WANTS
TO GET HOME AND SEE THEIR KIDS?
- SO PLEASE DON'T TELL ME
I DON'T KNOW WHERE MY KID IS.
- ALL I'M SAYING
IS THAT MAGGIE CLAIMS
THAT NO ONE ELSE IS INVOLVED.
BUT WHAT IF SHE'S LYING AGAIN
AND THERE IS SOMEONE ELSE
INVOLVED?
YOU KNOW,
A BOYFRIEND, A HUSBAND.
SOMEONE THAT GOT DUMPED WHEN
SOMETHING BETTER CAME ALONG.
- OF COURSE. WHY WOULDN'T SHE?
- WELL, YEAH, I'M A GOOD GUY,
YOU KNOW.
SO I'M THINKIN' THAT MAYBE
YOU CAN BREAK INTO HER HOUSE
AGAIN FOR ME
AND SEE IF YOU CAN
FIND SOME, UH--
- WAY OUT OF THIS FOR YOU?
I DON'T THINK SO.
- NO, I WAS GONNA SAY
FIND SOME EVIDENCE OF WHO
THE FATHER IS, BUT FORGET IT.
I'LL FIND SOMEBODY
WHO WANTS AN ADVENTURE.
[whispering] GEORGE MICHAEL,
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO GET AWAY
FROM UNCLE BUSTER?
- I'D REALLY LIKE THAT.
- GOOD. SHH, SHH, SHH.
narrator: AND SO,
WITH HIS SON'S HELP,
MICHAEL WENT TO MAGGIE'S
TO FIND SOME EVIDENCE
OF ANOTHER MAN.
- IT'S ANOTHER
BLUTH BOY ADVENTURE.
WE'RE LIKE A TEAM.
WE'RE LIKE
RED MCGIBBON AND BULLET.
- WHO?
- THEY'RE THIS OLD, UH--
NEVER MIND. OKAY, LISTEN.
ANYTHING YOU FIND IN THERE--
NAME, PHONE NUMBER--
YOU BRING IT OUT TO DADDY,
ALL RIGHT?
- YOU MEAN YOU'RE NOT
GOING IN WITH ME?
- HMM? NO.
I CAN'T FIT THROUGH
THAT DOGGY DOOR.
BUT I AM GONNA RISK BEING
CAUGHT OUT HERE.
BE CAREFUL.
- OKAY, I GOT A PHONE NUMBER.
LET'S GO. DRIVE.
LET'S GO. HIT THE GAS.
- YOU DIDN'T EVEN GO INSIDE.
- IT WAS TAPED TO THE DOOR.
- IT'S PROBABLY
THE SPARKLETTS GUY.
LISTEN, IT'S OKAY.
I'M TELLING YOU.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE SCARED ABOUT.
I'M NOT GETTING THAT VIBE.
HEY!
- EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
- YES, OFFICER.
JUST WAITING TO SEE
IF MAGGIE'S HOME.
- OH.
I WAS MAKING SURE THERE
WASN'T ANOTHER BREAK-IN.
MY PARTNER IS INSIDE
WITH HIS GUN DRAWN.
EVERYTHING'S GONNA
BE JUST FINE.
- CLOSE CALL THERE, BULLET.
I'M SO SORRY ABOUT THAT.
BUT LISTEN, I THINK--
I THINK THAT YOU DO
HAVE SOMETHING HERE
WITH THIS PHONE NUMBER.
"REALLY EAGER
TO HEAR FROM YOU."
YOU KNOW, THAT'S SOMETHING
A GUY WOULD SAY
IF HE WAS THE FATHER
OF HER CHILD
AND THE MOTHER STOPPED CALLING
'CAUSE SHE FOUND
A REALLY GOOD GUY.
I THINK THIS IS HIM.
I'M GETTIN' THAT VIBE.
WE'RE HAVIN' SOME FUN,
AREN'T WE?
I'M REALLY SORRY
ABOUT THAT.
narrator: GOB ARRIVED
AT THE DOCK
HOPING TO RECOVER
HIS BROTHER'S MISSING HAND.
- I'M LOOKIN' FOR THE SEAL
THAT'S GOT THE TASTE
FOR KITTY BLOOD.
[cats meowing]
I'LL PAY YOU HANDSOMELY.
[meowing]
narrator: IN FACT,
THE SKIPPER HAD ALREADY
RENTED HIS BOAT
TO BE SHOT IN MAEBY'S FILM.
SO NEITHER HE NOR GOB
WERE PREPARED...
- [screaming]
narrator: FOR THE CHALLENGES
OF USING CATS TO CATCH A SEAL.
[cat howling]
- GOD!
IT'S LIKE HERDING CATS.
[cat screeches]
HERE'S YOUR KITTY CAT.
AAH! FINE!
YOU DON'T GET TO BE BAIT!
- WHY ARE THERE CATS
IN THE SHOT?
- THIS IS THE CAMERA BOAT.
CAN YOU LOSE THE [bleeps] CATS,
PLEASE?
- UNCLE GOB?
- MAEBY?
narrator: AND MICHAEL
TRACED THE PHONE NUMBER
HE FOUND ON THE NOTE
TO AN ADDRESS.
- THANK YOU, MR. PARMESAN.
OKAY.
IN THERE IS THE FATHER
OF THE CHILD
THAT MAGGIE WANTS ME
TO HELP HER RAISE.
AND HE PROBABLY DOESN'T KNOW
THAT SHE'S GOT
ANOTHER MAN INVOLVED.
SO I WANT YOU TO STAY HERE
AND ENJOY THE ADVENTURE
FROM THE CAR.
THIS ONE COULD GET
A LITTLE UGLY.
AND, HEY, I'D LIKE TO SEE
THAT COP OF MAGGIE'S
DO DETECTIVE WORK THIS GOOD,
HUH?
[knocking at door]
OH, COME ON.
IS THIS YOUR PHONE NUMBER?
- HEY, I TOLD YOU AT THE BAR.
I LEFT THAT ON MAGGIE'S DOOR.
AND WHY ARE YOU HANGIN'
AROUND MAGGIE'S HOUSE,
ANYWAY?
- I--I'M SORRY.
I'M IN THIS CRAZY RELATIONSHIP.
SHE WANTS ME TO RAISE THIS CHILD
WITH HER
BECAUSE THERE'S NO FATHER.
- NO FATHER?
- I THOUGHT I'D COME HERE--
- THERE'S A FATHER.
THERE'S TWO FATHERS. DAVID!
- I'M MAKING GRAVY.
- THAT BITCH IS GONNA
KEEP OUR CHILD.
- [gasps]
I KNEW SHE WAS UP TO SOMETHING.
- [singing] HOT COPS
[hisses] HOT
narrator: MICHAEL HAD TRACKED
DOWN THE COUPLE
WHO'D HIRED MAGGIE
TO CARRY THEIR CHILD.
- SO THAT'S WHY YOU GUYS
ARE STAKING OUT HER HOUSE.
- SHE HASN'T RETURNED OUR CALLS.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT HER
I JUST DON'T TRUST.
- I'LL SAY.
SHE SAID SHE DOESN'T KNOW
WHO THE FATHER IS.
- IN A FUNNY WAY, NEITHER DO WE.
- WE JUST GAVE HER
A MIXED COCKTAIL,
TWO PARTS TAYLOR...
- TWO PARTS CARTER...
- AND LET HER DO HER THING.
- WE DECIDED WE NEVER
WANT TO KNOW
WHICH OF US
IS THE "REAL" FATHER.
- WELL, WHY SHOULD YOU?
I JUST HOPE YOU FIND OUT WHICH
ONE OF YOU CAN BREAST-FEED.
[chuckles]
- YOU KNOW,
WE'RE IN A LOVING RELATIONSHIP,
AND JUST BECAUSE
WE DON'T HAVE BREASTS
DOES NOT MEAN
WE CANNOT NOURISH OUR CHILD.
- I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO--
I DON'T WANT YOU GUYS TO WORRY
ABOUT GETTING THAT CHILD BACK
FROM MAGGIE,
BECAUSE I'M GONNA HELP YOU.
- WOW.
WHAT A...GOOD GUY.
- I KNOW, AND FOR ONCE,
I'M ONE LIE AHEAD
OF MAGGIE LIZER'S LIES.
narrator: IN FACT, MICHAEL WAS
ONE LIE BEHIND HER.
- AND WHAT IF I TOLD YOU
THAT LORETTA WAS NOT FAT,
BUT ACTUALLY
A VERY GREEDY WOMAN
IN A VERY CHEAP FAT SUIT?
WHAT, DO YOU THINK
I'M KIDDING, HUH?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- OKAY, SO SHE'S FAT.
- YOUR HONOR,
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE!
- WOW, DID I LOSE THIS ONE.
- MR. ZUCKERKORN, YOU'VE BEEN
WARNED ABOUT TOUCHING.
- YOU SAID SPANKING.
- I WANT THIS CASE
THROWN OUT IMMEDIATELY.
- [grunts]
narrator: IN FACT,
LORETTA WASN'T OVERWEIGHT...
- OH, NO, MAGGIE,
MY WATER JUST BROKE!
- QUICKLY, YOUR HONOR.
QUICKLY THROW IT OUT.
narrator: BUT WAS
CARRYING THE CHILD
THAT MAGGIE WAS SUPPOSED TO.
YOU SEE, IT WAS LORETTA'S URINE
THAT TOBIAS AND LINDSAY
ENDED UP TESTING,
A FACT THEY MISSED WHEN THEY
WERE MAKING OUT IN THE SHOWER.
AND MAGGIE DID BUY THE FAT SUIT
TO SERVE AS HER PREGNANCY BELLY.
- ALL RIGHT,
THIS IS GOIN' BACK.
narrator: BUT SOON UPGRADED TO
A HIGHER-QUALITY LATEX MODEL.
- IT'S TIME!
- IS THERE A DOCTOR
IN THE HOUSE?
- OH, MY GOD!
MY WATER BROKE TOO!
I'M IN LABOR!
narrator: MAGGIE WASN'T,
BUT HAD NO CHOICE BUT TO PRETEND
TO DELIVER AT THE SAME TIME.
AND GOB CAUGHT UP WITH MAEBY
AND MADE A CONFESSION.
- I THINK I'M RESPONSIBLE
FOR BUSTER'S HAND.
- YEAH, AND I'M RESPONSIBLE
FOR AN $80 MILLION MOVIE
WITHOUT AN ENDING.
- I KNOW THOSE PROBLEMS SEEM BIG
WHEN YOU'RE A KID, MAEBY.
- LOOK, THIS IS KIND OF WEIRD
ADVICE FOR ME TO BE GIVING,
BUT WHY DON'T YOU
JUST TELL HIM THE TRUTH?
I MEAN,
HE'LL RESPECT YOU FOR IT.
- THANKS, MAEBY.
- OKAY, NOW I'M JUST LYING
FOR NO REASON.
narrator: AND MICHAEL ARRIVED
AT THE COURTHOUSE
ONLY TO DISCOVER THAT MAGGIE
HAD ALREADY BEEN RUSHED
TO THE HOSPITAL.
AND BACK AT THE PENTHOUSE,
LUCILLE WAS PRAYING FOR
THE SECOND TIME IN HER LIFE.
- LORD, LET BUSTER
FORGET EVERYTHING.
AND IF YOU NEED TO TAKE ANOTHER
HAND TO MAKE THAT HAPPEN,
PLEASE MAKE IT GOB'S.
narrator: IT WAS AT
THAT EXACT MOMENT
THAT BUSTER DID FORGET
HE'D LOST HIS HAND.
- OH! NO, STOP IT!
STOP IT! STOP IT!
OH, YOU CAUGHT MY TENDON
IN YOUR CLAW!
- MY CLAW? AW, GOD!
[hysterical whimpering]
I'M A MONSTER!
[screaming]
NO!
[screams]
[bleep]
- WHOSE IDEA WAS
THE TEMPORARY HAND?
- BUSTER!
- HI, THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU NEED TO KNOW.
- THERE'S NOTHING
HE NEEDS TO KNOW.
TAKE HIS HAND. TAKE IT NOW!
- IT WAS MY FAULT.
IT WAS MY SEAL.
I RELEASED HIM,
AND HE BIT OFF YOUR HAND.
WOW. TRUTH FEELS GOOD.
[chuckling]
- YOU DID THIS TO ME?
- YEAH.
narrator: AND GOB WAS
ABOUT TO EXPERIENCE SOMETHING
THAT DIDN'T FEEL THAT GOOD.
- [screaming]
- NO, BUSTER! OH!
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
NOTIFIED THE POLICEMEN
THAT MAGGIE WAS IN THE HOSPITAL.
- I WILL MEET YOU THERE.
- WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
- I'M GETTING GOOSEBUMPS.
- HI. OKAY.
I'M GONNA GO IN THERE
WITH MAGGIE.
AS FAR AS I KNOW, SHE'S ALREADY
HAD THE KID, OKAY?
WE'RE HAVIN' SOME
ADVENTURE THOUGH, HUH?
YOU CAN'T SAY
WE'RE NOT HAVIN' FUN.
- DON'T SMOKE, SONNY.
[wheezing cough]
- MICHAEL.
OH, I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
- IS THIS OUR
LITTLE BUNDLE OF...
TWO GAY COPS' BABY?
[shushing]
- HERE IT IS.
THIS CAME FROM OUR CUP.
- THAT FELLOW
WAS IN OUR CUP ONCE.
- HERE'S SOMETHING I THINK
YOU BOTH NEED TO HAVE.
- BOY, YOU JUST CANNOT GET OFF
THE BREAST THING, CAN YOU?
- OKAY, WHERE'S THE BABY?
- I'M NOT PREGNANT.
- BUT WE PAID YOU
TO DO THIS, MAGGIE.
- I KNOW, AND I WANTED TO,
BUT THEN IT TURNS OUT I
COULDN'T GET PREGNANT.
AND I HAD THIS CLIENT--
YOU KNOW, WE WERE WORKING
ON THE FAT CASE.
SO I--
HEY, I OUTSOURCED IT, OKAY?
- AND YOU WEREN'T GONNA LET
THESE NICE GUYS HAVE A BABY?
YOU WERE GONNA
HAVE US RAISE IT?
- OF COURSE NOT.
I'M GONNA GIVE 'EM THEIR BABY.
I NEVER THOUGHT YOU'D
STICK AROUND.
- I'M NOT GOIN' ANYWHERE,
BABY.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH ME?
[machine beeping]
- OH! HERE IT COMES!
HERE COMES THE BABY!
IS THAT THE HEAD?
narrator: LORETTA HAD HER BABY,
AND THE NEW FAMILY
COULDN'T HAVE BEEN HAPPIER.
AND MICHAEL REUNITED
WITH HIS SON.
- YOU DISAPPOINTED?
- YOU KIDDIN' ME?
YOU'RE THE ONLY SON
I'VE EVER NEEDED.
[bell dings]
- THAT'S ALL THE ADVENTURE
I'VE EVER NEEDED.
- OKAY, SON,
I'M GONNA MEET YOU AT THE CAR.
"M." MAIN FLOOR.
NO ADVENTURE THERE.
narrator: BUT "M" DIDN'T STAND
FOR "MAIN FLOOR."
- DR. WARD TO THE MORGUE,
PLEASE.
DR. WARD TO THE MORGUE, PLEASE.
STAT.
[tool whirring]
narrator: AND MICHAEL SAID
GOOD-BYE TO MAGGIE.
- I KNOW. I'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
- WELL, WE OBVIOUSLY BOTH DO.
WE OBVIOUSLY BOTH CRAVE SOME
CRAZY COMPLICATION IN OUR LIVES.
WHEN WE'RE TOGETHER,
IT IS LIKE--
- MAGIC?
- I WAS GONNA SAY "TRAIN WRECK."
- WE HAVE TO MAKE A VOW, OKAY?
THIS IS OVER.
NO MORE LYING.
NO DECEIT, NO SEX. EVERYTHING.
- NO MORE LIES.
narrator: BUT THAT TOO
TURNED OUT TO BE A LIE.
ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
BUSTER AND GOB FIND THEMSELVES
CLOSER THAN EVER.
- AND THERE YOU ARE.
WE'VE REMOVED THE HOOK,
AND THERE'S BEEN NO DAMAGE.
- OH, THANK GOD.
- YEAH, HE'S GONNA BE FINE.
BUT UNFORTUNATELY, YOU'VE STILL
GOT A HOOK IN YOUR ASS.
narrator: AND MAGGIE
GETS A BIG SURPRISE.
- YOU HAVE GOT
TO BE KIDDING ME.
- [singing] HOT COPS
WE'LL CLEAN UP THE TOWN
WE'LL TURN THAT OLD FROWN
UPSIDE DOWN
HOT COPS
WE'RE AIMING TO PLEASE
YOU KNOW WE'LL GET DOWN
ON OUR KNEES
WE'RE TAKING ON
THE BAD BOYS
WITH OUR LOADED GUNS
WE'LL PUMP YOU FULL
OF MOLTEN LEAD
BANG, BANG, YOU'RE DEAD
HOT COPS
JUST GIVE US A SQUEEZE
[hisses] HOT