male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING,
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH
HAD GOTTEN UP EARLY
IN THE HOPES
OF AVOIDING HIS FAMILY.
HIS MOTHER, HOWEVER,
WAS ALREADY DRESSED,
MADE UP,
AND WAITING FOR HIM.
- GOOD MORNING.
- OOH!
narrator: WHICH PUT
HER WAKE-UP TIME
IN THE 3:00, 3:30 AREA.
- I COULDN'T SLEEP.
I ALWAYS GET THIS WAY
BEFORE MOTHERBOY.
- OH, GOD.
IT'S MOTHERBOY ALREADY?
narrator: MOTHERBOY WAS
A DINNER DANCE AIMED
AT PROMOTING MOTHER-SON BONDING.
LUCILLE HAD GONE OVER 25 TIMES
WITH BUSTER,
AND ON A FEW OCCASIONS,
HAD WON CUTEST COUPLE.
AS ONE ENTERED SEXUAL MATURITY,
AND THE OTHER ONE LEFT IT,
IT BECAME HARDER TO WIN.
- I'M SO HOT.
- IF YOU WERE HOT,
MOTHER, WE WOULD WIN.
- IT'S NOT JUST MOTHERBOY.
IT'S MOTHERBOY XXX.
AND I THINK WITH YOU,
I'VE GOT A SHOT.
- OH, NO.
BUSTER, FOR THE FIRST TIME EVER,
DOESN'T WANT TO DO THIS?
- NO, NO, HE DOES.
IT'S JUST,
HE'S BEEN SO MOPEY.
- WELL, THAT COULD HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE FACT
THAT A SEAL ATE HIS HAND.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
- I THINK THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
- WHO KNOWS?
narrator: IT WAS THAT.
IT HAD HAPPENED WEEKS EARLIER
WHEN BUSTER
WENT SWIMMING IN THE OCEAN
AGAINST HIS MOTHER'S WISHES.
- [screaming]
narrator: HE HAD BECOME HAUNTED
BY THE LOSS...
- [gasps]
narrator: SEEING REMINDERS
OF THE ACCIDENT EVERYWHERE.
- [gasps]
[gasps and screams]
MOTHER, I CAN'T SLEEP.
I MAY NOT BE ABLE TO GO
TO DANCE PRACTICE TODAY.
- I'M GOING OUT.
ZIP ME UP.
I MEAN,
LOOK HOW HE ZIPS NOW.
- I KNOW WHAT THIS IS.
YOU'RE EMBARRASSED BY HIM,
AREN'T YOU?
YOU SPENT YOUR WHOLE LIFE
OVER-MOTHERING THE GUY,
AND WHEN HE FINALLY NEEDS YOU,
YOU'RE NOT THERE.
- WELL, I DON'T SEE YOU
SPENDING TIME WITH HIM.
narrator: THE BLUTH CHILDREN
HAD BEEN UNEASY
ABOUT MISSING LIMBS
SINCE THEIR FATHER USED
A ONE-ARMED MAN
TO TEACH THEM LESSONS.
- THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T YELL.
- AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I'M GOING TO SEE BUSTER TODAY.
SO YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO FIND
A DIFFERENT DANCE PARTNER
FOR MOTHERBOY.
- GOD. NOT THAT "I'M IN LOVE
WITH MY MOTHER" DANCE THING.
I'M SO GLAD THERE WASN'T
ONE OF THOSE
FOR DADDIES AND DAUGHTERS.
- OF COURSE THEY HAVE
FATHER-DAUGHTER DANCES.
- THEY DO?
HE NEVER TOOK ME?
- IT WAS BEFORE
WE DID YOUR NOSE. TOODLE-OOH.
- YOU'RE UP AWFUL EARLY.
- YEAH, WELL, MY MARRIAGE
IS FALLING APART.
TOBIAS IS BACK WITH CARL.
narrator:
TOBIAS HAD GOTTEN A CALL
FROM HIS ONE-TIME ACTING
TEACHER, CARL WEATHERS.
- HE'S DIRECTING SOMETHING
FOR TV,
BUT HE THINKS
HE MIGHT HAVE A PART FOR ME.
IF THIS TAKES OFF,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO BUY YOU
THE HAPPINESS THAT YOU DESERVE.
- HE SAID THE SAME THING
WHEN HE GOT CAST
AS FRIGHTENED INMATE NUMBER TWO
IN THAT FILM
HE GOT FIRED FROM.
narrator: HE HAD EVEN
GOTTEN A VANITY PLATE MADE UP
ANNOUNCING THE ACHIEVEMENT.
AND THIS WASN'T THE FIRST TIME.
- HE'S SO CLUELESS.
HE'S NOT YOUR REAL
"TAKE CHARGE" HUSBAND.
- LINDSAY, YOU'RE STILL LOOKING
FOR SOMEBODY LIKE DADDY, OKAY?
LET'S NOT FORGET THAT HE
WAS ALSO DISMISSIVE
AND DISINTERESTED.
- NO. NO, HE HAD GOOD QUALITIES.
narrator: ACTUALLY, GEORGE, SR.
WAS SECRETLY LIVING
IN THE ATTIC ABOVE THEM
AND WAS STARVED FOR COMPANY.
- NOW,
WHO WANTS TO TAKE
THEIR TOP OFF?
narrator: WHEN GEORGE MICHAEL
AND MAEBY CAME IN.
- SO YOU AND ANN
ARE ACTUALLY GOING
ON A CHRISTIAN CAMPING TRIP?
- IT'S CALLED THE PROMISE LAND.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO MAKE PROMISES
ABOUT YOUR RELATIONSHIP
AS A TRIBUTE TO THE GENERATIONS
THAT PRECEDED YOU.
HEY, THERE'S BOOZE IN THIS.
- THAT'S THE PROMISE LAND
THAT ANN'S TAKING YOU TO?
YOU'RE GONNA NEED THIS
MORE THAN POLLY HERE.
- THAT FAT ONE'S POLLY?
- HEY, WHAT ARE YOU KIDS
DOIN' UP HERE?
- WE'RE JUST LOOKIN'
FOR THE CAMPING STUFF.
HEY, DO YOU KNOW WHERE THE
PUMP IS FOR THE AIR MATTRESS?
- I HAD TO TAKE ALL PUMPS
OUT OF HERE A LONG TIME AGO.
TAKE THIS DOWN TO
THE KITCHEN, WILL YOU?
I THINK IT'S GETTING A LITTLE
TOO RISKY KEEPING YOU UP HERE.
- YEAH, YOU KNOW WHAT'S RISKY?
LETTIN' YOUR SON
GO ON THAT CHURCH THING.
- WELL, HER NAME'S ANN, DAD, AND
HE'S NOT "GOING" ON HER, OKAY?
THEY'RE JUST FRIENDS.
- NOT FOR LONG.
THEY'RE MAKING PROMISES
TO EACH OTHER.
IT'S ALL THAT FIDELITY
AND PLEDGING YOURSELF
TO A WOMAN GARBAGE.
I WINE 'EM AND DINE 'EM,
BUT I DON'T LET 'EM
TELL ME WHAT TO DO.
I DON'T LET 'EM
- OKAY, I SHOULD'VE NEVER TAKEN
THE PUMPS OUT OF HERE.
LISTEN, UNLIKE YOU,
I RESPECT MY SON'S CHOICES.
GEORGE MICHAEL, I DON'T THINK
YOU SHOULD BE GOING
ON THIS PROMISE LAND THING.
- WHAT? WHY?
IS THIS BECAUSE I'D MISS SCHOOL?
- NO.
- YOU GET
TO MISS SCHOOL FOR THAT?
narrator:
AND THAT'S WHEN MAEBY DECIDED
TO BECOME A DEVOUT CHRISTIAN.
- DO YOU GUYS KNOW WHERE I
COULD GET ONE
OF THOSE GOLD NECKLACES
WITH THE "T" ON IT?
- THAT'S A CROSS.
- ACROSS FROM WHERE?
- UM, IT'S NOT ABOUT SCHOOL,
PAL. IT'S MORE ABOUT FAMILY.
YOUR UNCLE BUSTER'S BEEN
VERY DEPRESSED LATELY,
AND YOU HAVEN'T VISITED HIM.
FAMILY FIRST.
OR DID THEY NOT TEACH YOU THAT
AT THE PROMISE LAND?
- I DON'T KNOW.
YOU WON'T LET ME GO.
- [clicks tongue] ATTABOY.
narrator: MICHAEL THEN WENT
TO THE OFFICE,
WHERE HE RAN INTO GOB.
- BARRY COME BY YET? I NEED TO
TALK TO HIM ABOUT MY DIVORCE.
narrator: GOB HAD ONCE
GOTTEN MARRIED ON A DARE,
A FACT HE'D ONLY REMEMBERED
WHEN HE WAS SERVED
WITH DIVORCE PAPERS.
- THAT COW IS GOING AFTER ME.
- YOUR WIFE? SHE WAS SUPER-THIN.
- SHE WAS?
- YEAH.
- WHAT ABOUT HER CANS?
SHE HAVE BIG CANS?
- YOU DON'T REMEMBER HER AT ALL,
DO YOU?
- HEY, IT WAS ONE NIGHT
OF WILD PASSION.
- AND YET YOU DIDN'T
NOTICE HER BODY.
- I LIKE TO LOOK IN THE MIRROR.
- OKAY, THAT WOULD BE DISGUSTING
IF YOU'D ACTUALLY SLEPT WITH
HER, BUT I DON'T THINK YOU DID.
- I DID, AND IT WAS DISGUSTING.
narrator: THEY DIDN'T,
BUT IT WOULD HAVE BEEN.
- ANYWAY, REMEMBER THAT SEAL
OF HERS
THAT I RELEASED INTO THE OCEAN?
BIT OFF BUSTER'S HAND?
- VAGUELY.
- HER LAWYERS ARE CLAIMING
THAT THE SEAL'S WORTH 250 GRAND.
AND THAT'S NOT EVEN
INCLUDING BUSTER'S SWATCH.
- LISTEN, GOB, IF YOU ADMIT
IN COURT
THAT YOU NEVER
CONSUMMATED THE MARRIAGE,
YOU CAN GET IT ANNULLED
AND WALK AWAY FREE AND CLEAR.
YOU JUST CAN'T DEAL
WITH THE FACT
THAT I'VE GOT A SUPER-THIN
WIFE WITH HUGE CANS.
[elevator bell dings]
- ALL RIGHT. WHO'S READY TO SHOW
THEIR LAWYER SOME LOVE?
- THE SEAL?
- HA! MUST'VE HAD
A TRACKING DEVICE ON IT.
SOMEONE TRACKED IT ALL THE WAY
TO A DOCK IN DANA POINT.
- YOU KNOW, IF THAT HAND IS
STILL INTACT INSIDE THE SEAL,
BUSTER'S GOT A SHOT
AT A TRANSPLANT.
- AT THE VERY LEAST, WE CAN GET
BUSTER'S SWATCH BACK, RIGHT?
UP TOP. NO?
narrator: AND TOBIAS MET WITH
CARL WEATHERS AT BURGER KING.
- THANKS FOR MEETING ME DOWN
HERE AT BURGER KING.
I'M TRYIN' TO GET THEM
TO UNDERWRITE A NEW
TV PROJECT I'M WORKIN' ON.
GET SOME MONEY IN EXCHANGE
FOR SETTIN' A SCENE
HERE IN BURGER KING.
- AS LONG AS YOU
DON'T DRAW ATTENTION TO IT.
- I'M DIRECTING AN EPISODE
OF THE SERIES "SCANDAL MAKERS."
IT'S ABOUT THE BLUTH FAMILY
AND YOUR FATHER-IN-LAW'S
ESCAPE FROM JUSTICE.
I PLAY THE LEAD--
A BOUNTY HUNTER, NAME OF ICE.
- OH, NO.
YOU WANT ME TO PLAY MYSELF,
DON'T YOU?
I SWORE I'D NOT GO REALITY.
- NO, I ALREADY GOT A GREAT GUY
NAMED DAVE ATTELL TO PLAY YOU.
I WASN'T ACTUALLY HERE
TO ASK YOU TO BE IN IT.
I'M LOOKIN' FOR SOMEBODY IN YOUR
FAMILY TO SIGN A RELEASE.
- I COULD NOT BETRAY MY FAMILY
LIKE THAT.
- COME ON, MAN.
I'VE GOT EVERY PART CAST
EXCEPT FOR GEORGE, SR.
- I WANT THAT PART.
- THEN SIGN OVER THE RIGHTS.
I'M GONNA GO GET A NEW SODA.
DID YOU KNOW THAT YOU CAN GET
A REFILL
ON ANY DRINK YOU WANT HERE,
AND IT'S FREE?
[laughs]
- IT'S A WONDERFUL RESTAURANT.
narrator: IT SURE IS.
GEORGE MICHAEL,
MEANWHILE, SPENT AN AFTERNOON
WITH HIS UNCLE,
AT HIS FATHER'S SUGGESTION.
- OH, GOD!
- I KEEP FORGETTING ABOUT THIS.
- OH, ME TOO.
- WELL, THAT'S A DO-OVER.
SO WHO SHOULD GO FIRST?
I KNOW. LET'S
ROCK-PAPER-SCISSORS FOR IT.
- NO! YOU WOULD'VE--
YOU WOULD'VE WON THAT, SO--
- OH.
- GEORGE MICHAEL--
BUSTER,
DID YOU AT LEAST OFFER
YOUR NEPHEW A BOWL OF SOUP?
- YES, MOTHER, I DID.
CAN I OPEN
A CAN OF SOUP FOR YOU?
- CAN IT OPEN A CAN?
- CAN WHAT OPEN A CAN?
- OH, GOD.
ACTUALLY, I JUST WANTED
TO SPEND SOME TIME
WITH MY KNUCKLE BUSTER.
- SEE, MOTHER? NOT EVERYBODY
IS AFRAID OF ME.
- OH, MY GOD.
- AREN'T YOU THE SWEETEST THING,
SPENDING SOME TIME WITH
WHAT'S LEFT OF YOUR UNCLE.
- I WAS SUPPOSED TO GO AWAY TO
THE PROMISE LAND THIS WEEKEND,
BUT MY DAD DIDN'T WANT ME TO.
- FAMILY FIRST.
- WELL, YOU'VE DONE
YOUR DUTY THIS WEEK.
YOU'RE A VERY SYMPATHETIC
YOUNG MAN.
VERY SYMPATHETIC.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU DESERVE TO GO OUT OF TOWN
THIS WEEKEND,
AND I'M TAKING YOU.
- REALLY?
Narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
SHOULD HAVE REALIZED
BY THE SAILOR SUIT
LUCILLE DRESSED HIM IN
THAT HE WASN'T GOING NORTH
TO THE PROMISE LAND.
- [singing]
ANYONE ELSE BUT ME
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU DON'T KNOW
THIS SONG, GEORGE MICHAEL.
[singing] NO, NO, NO
narrator:
NO, HE WAS GOING SOUTH.
SOUTH TO MOTHERBOY.
narrator: AND MICHAEL AND GOB
HEADED OUT
TO FIND THE SEAL
WITH THE TRACKING DEVICE.
- I GUESS WE SHOULD CALL BUSTER
AND HAVE HIM MEET US
AT THE DOCK, RIGHT?
- I GUESS SO.
[all screaming]
- OR WE COULD MAKE SURE
IT'S THE RIGHT SEAL FIRST?
I MEAN, WHY GET HIS HOPES UP?
- YEAH, THAT'S BETTER.
- KNOCK, KNOCK.
- OH, GOD!
- MONSTER!
- HEY, BROTHERS.
- BUSTER.
- MONSTER!
- SORRY ABOUT THE WINDOW.
- NOT A PROBLEM.
- I REALLY HATE
THIS STUPID HOOK.
BUT I CERTAINLY CAN'T WALK
AROUND LIKE THIS.
- WHY NOT?
- VERY HANDSOME.
SO LISTEN,
WE WERE JUST GONNA CALL YOU.
WE THINK WE KNOW
WHERE THE SEAL IS.
- THE SEAL THAT
DID THIS TO ME?
- YEAH.
- TAKE ME!
- YES. THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
I'M GONNA GO WITH BARRY.
NO, NO, YOU SHOULD GET IN HERE.
I'LL JUST GO WITH BARRY.
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH ROOM
FOR YOU AND ME AND THE STUMP
AND THE THING--STUFF.
BARRY!
narrator: TOBIAS HAD GOTTEN
HIS FIRST SPEAKING ROLE
SIMPLY BY SIGNING AWAY
THE LIFE RIGHTS
OF EVERYONE HE LOVED.
AND NOW HE NEEDED SOME RESEARCH.
- I'M GEORGE, SR.
OOH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S THE VOICE.
I'VE GOT THE VOICE.
- THAT'S NOT MY VOICE.
- OH, MY GOD!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M HAVIN'
A [bleep] TEA PARTY.
WHAT DOES IT LOOK LIKE?
I LIVE HERE.
YOU TELL ANYBODY, YOU ARE DEAD.
narrator: TOBIAS SAW
THE RAW POWER OF GEORGE, SR.
- STOP LICKING MY HAND,
YOU HORSE'S ASS.
narrator: A POWER HE NEEDED
THE MAN TO TEACH HIM.
- THAT'S IT.
narrator: SO HE EXPLAINED
THE PROJECT,
AND GEORGE, SR.
AGREED ON ONE CONDITION.
- IF YOU PLAY ME,
YOU GOT TO PLAY ME LIKE A MAN
AND NOT SOME MINCING LITTLE
POLLY OR NELLIE.
I GET THOSE NAMES CONFUSED.
APOLOGIES. APOLOGIES ALL AROUND.
narrator: AND THE SEARCH
FOR BUSTER'S HAND CONTINUED.
- I WOULD LOVE TO BE ABLE
TO SAY
"LOOK WHAT I'VE
HAD REATTACHED
WHILE YOU AND GEORGE MICHAEL
WERE OFF TO MOTHERBOY."
- MOTHERBOY? WAIT A MINUTE.
MOM TOOK HIM TO MOTHERBOY?
- [laughs]
HE COULDN'T WAIT TO SWOOP IN
AND THROW ON THAT SAILOR SUIT,
BECAUSE HE'S NOT DAMAGED GOODS.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T WANT HIM DOING THAT.
YOU GOT TO GO WITH ME DOWN THERE
AND HELP ME GET HIM, ALL RIGHT?
THAT PLACE IS YOUR SCENE.
- FACE IT, MICHAEL.
THEY'VE WON.
HE'S THE NEW BUSTER.
narrator:
THIS WAS THE WORST THING
MICHAEL COULD POSSIBLY HEAR.
- OH, I'M SO SORRY.
FALSE ALARM.
WHAT THEY TRACKED DOWN
WAS A SHARK,
AND HE MUST'VE BITTEN OFF
THE PART OF THE SEAL
WITH THE TRACKING DEVICE ON IT.
LEFT FLIPPER.
- SO THE SEAL LOST
HIS HAND TOO.
- YEAH, POOR GUY'S PROBABLY OUT
THERE WITHOUT A FLIPPER,
SWIMMING AROUND IN A CIRCLE,
FREAKING OUT HIS WHOLE FAMILY.
- THAT TRACKING DEVICE TELLS ME
HE WAS RAISED IN CAPTIVITY.
THERE'S NO WAY HE STOOD
A CHANCE OUT IN THE REAL WORLD.
- SEE THAT, BUSTER?
HE WAS A VICTIM TOO.
YOU BOTH WERE TOO SHELTERED
TO LEARN HOW
TO PROTECT YOURSELVES,
AND WE CAN'T LET THAT HAPPEN
TO GEORGE MICHAEL.
- I WILL HELP YOU, MICHAEL.
WE'VE GOT TO RESCUE YOUR SON.
- AND I'VE GOT TO
STAPLE THIS TO A SEAL.
- AND I'VE SKIPPED BREAKFAST,
SO I'M OFF TO BURGER KING.
narrator: AND LUCILLE ARRIVED
AT THE HOTEL
WHERE MOTHERBOY
WAS TAKING PLACE.
- THIS IS NICE, SPENDING SOME
TIME, JUST THE TWO OF US.
OH, [bleeps] ME.
THE EXACT SAME COLOR.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
NOT TO WORRY.
GANGY BROUGHT SOME BACKUPS.
WE'LL GET A ROOM
SO WE CAN CHANGE.
YOU THINK ENOUGH TIME HAS PASSED
TO DO SONNY AND CHER?
- WHO?
- WE'RE HERE FOR MOTHERBOY.
- AND YOU DO REALIZE
THIS IS NOT THE BAND.
narrator: MOTHERBOY WAS ALSO
A HEAVY METAL BAND
THAT USED TO ROCK
PRETTY HARD IN THE '70s.
WE ARE LEGALLY OBLIGATED
TO MAKE THE DISTINCTION.
- YOU KNOW, MAYBE I SHOULD LET
MY DAD KNOW THAT WE'RE HERE.
- OH, HE'LL KNOW WHEN WE
BRING HOME THE TROPHY.
- YEAH, BUT MAYBE
I'LL JUST GIVE HIM A CALL.
- AND WHAT NAME SHALL WE
PUT THE ROOM UNDER?
- KARMOPOLIS.
narrator: AND LINDSAY
WAS ABOUT TO SEE
A TOBIAS WITH
THE RAW POWER OF GEORGE, SR.
- I SORT OF WANT TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT SOME THINGS.
- IT'S A LITTLE LATE
FOR TALK, LINDSAY.
I'M A MAN OF ACTION NOW.
YOU DON'T NEED THE CALORIES.
[whispering]
THIS ISN'T WORKING.
- IS IT MY IMAGINATION,
OR IS HE MORE COMMANDING
AND MANNISH?
IT'S LIKE, I DON'T KNOW,
MAYBE I DO WANT TO BE WITH HIM.
- THEN YOU SHOULD GO TO HIM.
FOR AS IT IS WRITTEN,
YOU SHALL BE WITH WHOM
YOU HAVE FORMED
A MORE PERFECT UNION
WITH UNDER GOD.
- [chuffs]
SHE'S RIGHT.
- THIS ISN'T WORKING.
- I'M SORRY. YOU'VE GOT
THE WRONG MOTHERBOY.
- YEAH, THIS LOOKS
LIKE THE PLACE.
- AND MICHAEL AND BUSTER
ARRIVED AT MOTHERBOY.
- EXCUSE ME. HAS A LUCILLE BLUTH
CHECKED IN?
- I HAVE NO ONE
BY THAT NAME.
- GOD.
SHE KNOWS YOU'RE AFTER HER.
- SHE DOES?
- WAIT A MINUTE.
I RECOGNIZE THOSE OUTFITS.
WE'RE GETTING YOU OUT OF HERE.
- THANK YOU! THANK YOU!
- OH, GOD! IT'S RED.
- TAKE ME WITH YOU!
NO, PLEASE! PLEASE!
- IT'S THE WRONG CHILD.
- WHERE DO WE GO NEXT?
- I WILL TELL YOU THIS, MICHAEL.
IF MOTHER SAW THOSE TWO,
SHE IS GOING TO CHANGE CLOTHES.
AND THAT MEANS
HE'LL BE ON THE BALCONY.
WHENEVER SHE CHANGED CLOTHES,
SHE MADE ME WAIT ON
THE BALCONY UNTIL ZIP-UP.
AND YET,
ANYTHING GOES AT BATH TIME.
[chuckles]
- LET'S CHECK THE BALCONIES.
narrator: AND BARRY PREPARED GOB
TO MEET WITH HIS WIFE.
- IF YOU REALLY WANT
TO SETTLE THIS, NOW, YOUR JOB
IS TO CONVINCE
THAT "WIFE" OF YOURS
THAT YOU ARE WILLING TO GO
IN FRONT OF THE JUDGE
AND ADMIT
THAT YOU NEVER HAD SEX.
- SHE HAS A NAME, BARRY.
YOU DON'T HAPPEN TO KNOW
WHAT IT IS BY THE WAY, DO YOU?
- THAT'S WHY I WANT TO SETTLE.
I'M NOT SUPER PREPARED.
- WELL, WE DID HAVE SEX.
AND I'M NOT A GREAT LIAR.
narrator: BOTH THINGS HE JUST
SAID WERE LIES.
- BUT IF YOU THINK
IT'LL SCARE HER OFF.
- I DO, AND IT WILL.
AND YOU DON'T WANT TO GO
IN FRONT OF THAT JUDGE.
I CAUGHT HIM IN A DRAG CLUB.
- WHAT WERE YOU DOIN' THERE?
- WOW. YOU SHOULD BE THE LAWYER.
narrator: AND SOON, MICHAEL
AND BUSTER SURVEYED THE HOTEL,
LOOKING FOR GEORGE MICHAEL.
- THERE'S A VERY BORED-LOOKING
LITTLE SONNY BONO
ON THAT BALCONY.
- OH, GOD. THAT MEANS
SHE'LL BE DRESSED LIKE CHER.
- I HAVE AN IDEA.
IT IS TIME I USED SOMETHING
I TRAINED FOR IN ARMY
BUT I NEVER GOT A CHANCE TO DO.
- BUSTER, YOU CANNOT ZIP-LINE
OVER THERE!
- EITHER I ZIP DOWN
OR HE ZIPS UP!
AND THAT IS A MIGHTY LONG ZIPPER
ON MOTHER'S CHER JUMPSUIT.
YOU HAVE TO GET ON
YOUR KNEES TO START IT.
- THIS IS MUCH LESS SCARY.
GODSPEED, BUSTER.
- [screaming]
[glass shattering]
- ONE, TWO, THREE--
- [screaming]
- YOU CAME FOR ME!
- ZIP ME UP.
[glass shattering]
- WE'RE SWITCHING ROOMS AGAIN.
AND COSTUMES.
narrator: TOBIAS HAD BEGUN WORK
ON THE SET OF "SCANDAL MAKERS."
- WHAT'S SO GREAT ABOUT TOBIAS
IS HE'S GOT THIS OBLIGATION
TO HIS WIFE AND DAUGHTER.
- WHOA. THIS GUY'S STRAIGHT?
- YEAH.
- THEN WHAT THE HELL AM I
WEARIN' THESE FOR? LOOK AT THAT.
- HEY, GANG. I'M SORRY.
I DON'T WANT
TO NOTE YOU TO DEATH,
BUT YOU SHOULD BE WEARING THOSE
UNDER YOUR PANTS.
- WHY?
- OH, IT'S A THING.
THERE'S DOZENS OF US.
- CARL, THIS WHOLE THING
IS STARTIN' TO FEEL
LIKE A REAL CAREER KILLER.
- YEAH, I KNOW, MAN.
- ALSO, I--
- TOBIAS, WHY DON'T YOU
GO LEARN YOUR LINES, MAN?
WORK ON THEM.
- DID I GET LINES? GOD!
THEY TOLD ME I WAS JUST JUMPING
ONTO A MOVING STAIR CAR.
- IF THAT MAN'S STRAIGHT,
THEN I AM SOBER.
- HI. UM, I'M WAITING
FOR "GAWB" BLUTH.
- I'M GOB BLUTH.
MY WIFE SEND YOU?
- I'M YOUR WIFE.
- I KNEW THAT.
NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN, USARMY.
YOU LOST A LOT OF WEIGHT
IN IRAQ,
ESPECIALLY UP IN
THE NORTHERN REGION.
- SO WHERE'S THE SEAL?
- HEY, THAT'S NOT MY PROBLEM.
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
WE WERE NEVER EVEN MARRIED.
MAYBE I'LL JUST SAY THAT
WE NEVER SEALED THE DEAL.
- YOU'RE WILLING TO ADMIT THAT?
- LIE ABOUT IT? YES.
- WOW.
I MIS-UNDERESTIMATED YOU.
YOU'VE GOT SOME COURAGE.
MAKES ME WONDER
WHAT I'M MISSING.
- YOU MEAN,
OTHER THAN YOUR CANS?
- NO. THEY'RE STILL HERE.
narrator: AND SO GOB
SET ABOUT CONSUMMATING
THE MARRIAGE HE'D FINALLY AGREED
TO CLAIM HE HADN'T.
- [laughing]
narrator:
AND BACK AT MOTHERBOY XXX,
LUCILLE WAS FINDING
HER NEW PARTNER AN ASSET.
- IS THIS YOUR SON?
- NO, I'M HIS GRANDMOTHER.
HE'S AN ORPHAN.
- OH, I'M SO SORRY.
WELL, YOU GUYS SHOULD WIN.
- WELL, I'M NOT AN ORPHAN.
I HAVE A DAD.
- WELL, GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
- WELL, THAT LITTLE BIT
OF HONESTY HELPED NOTHING.
YOU'D BETTER BRING IT
TO THE WALTZ, YOUNG MAN.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MICHAEL AND BUSTER
HAD RETRIEVED BUSTER'S HOOK
AND WERE STAKING OUT
THE SITUATION.
- GYPSIES.
- HEY.
- [groans]
- THEY'VE CHANGED INTO GYPSIES.
MY ARMY TRAINING
TELLS ME THAT THIS IS
GOING TO BE A HOT MISSION.
- ONE HOT MISSION.
- YES.
I CREATE A DIVERSION,
AND YOU GRAB
GEORGE MICHAEL AND GO.
WE NEED A NAME.
MAYBE
"OPERATION HOT MOTHER."
- NO, LET'S TRY TO TOP THAT.
narrator: THEY NEVER DID.
AND LATER, OPERATION
HOT MOTHER WAS UNDERWAY.
BUSTER WAS WAITING
FOR MICHAEL'S CUE
TO UNPLUG THE LIGHTS.
BUT THAT'S WHEN BUSTER
CAUGHT HIS HOOK ON A SANDBAG.
- HEY!
- [grunts]
[whimpering]
- AND NOW FROM THE LAND
OF GYPSIES,
LUCILLE BLUTH
AND HER ORPHANED GRANDSON.
- WHAT THE HELL'S GOIN' ON,
BUSTER? CUT THE LIGHTS!
- [Buster whimpering]
[people gasping]
- BUSTER?
- GRAB HIM!
TAKE THE GYPSY BOY!
- COME ON, I'M TAKING
YOU OUT OF HERE. LET'S GO.
- WHAT?
THEY HAVEN'T SERVED DINNER YET.
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
- YOU'RE NOT TAKING HIM.
- TAKE ME WITH YOU!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'? I CAN'T.
GET OFF OF ME.
BUSTER, LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
- I'M STUCK. GO.
TAKE THE BOY. GO.
- ALL RIGHT, MOTHERBOYS.
OUR CURTAIN SEEMS TO BE STUCK.
WE'RE GOING TO DO SOME FREESTYLE
WALTZING WHILE WE GET IT FIXED.
BOYS' CHOICE.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU'RE CHOOSING ME.
- NO, MOM.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT TO BRING HIM
TO THIS FREAK SHOW.
HE WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE VISITING BUSTER.
- NO, YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO BE VISITING BUSTER,
BUT YOU MADE YOUR SON DO IT
BECAUSE YOU DIDN'T WANT TO.
- YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO DO IT?
- YOU DIDN'T WANT TO?
NO. BUSTER, I--
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW
TO, UH, TREAT YOU, ALL RIGHT?
I THOUGHT THAT YOU
WOULD BE A LITTLE DIFFERENT,
BUT YOU'RE NOT.
I WAS WRONG, OKAY?
I'M SORRY.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE AS GOOD
A BROTHER AS YOU EVER WERE.
- [groaning]
THANK YOU.
- ALL RIGHT?
- YES. I AM NO DIFFERENT.
I AM THE SAME OLD MOTHERBOY.
GEORGE MICHAEL STILL
HAS A CHANCE. TAKE HIM!
- THANKS.
LET'S GO.
- BOYS' CHOICE?
THAT IS, IF YOU'RE NOT
EMBARRASSED TO TAKE MY HOOK.
- OF COURSE NOT.
I'M PETER PAN,
AND YOU'RE CAPTAIN HOOK.
WE'LL PRETEND IT'S A COSTUME.
LET'S DANCE.
narrator: AND THAT NIGHT,
MICHAEL,
HIS BROTHER, AND HIS SON
ARRIVED AT THE PROMISE LAND.
- ALL RIGHT.
- I APPRECIATE YOU TAKING ME
UP HERE TO SEE ANN.
- A PROMISE IS A PROMISE.
AND I'M GLAD THE THREE OF US
WERE ABLE TO SPEND
SOME TIME TOGETHER.
- OH, YEAH.
- AND I FINALLY FEEL GOOD
ABOUT MYSELF.
"SADDEST."
- AND I SAW SOME
OF THOSE PEOPLE.
THAT WAS A VERY
COMPETITIVE CATEGORY.
- OH, DON'T I KNOW IT.
- HERE WE GO.
- I CAN'T GET OUT, ACTUALLY.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT,"
LINDSAY FINDS HERSELF STRANGELY
COMPELLED TO BE WITH TOBIAS.
- I HAVE NEVER BEEN
MORE ATTRACTED TO YOU.
- WOW. THE SERVICE
SENT YOU OVER FAST.
- OH, GOD. I'M SO SORRY.
I'M IN THE WRONG TRAILER.
narrator: BUT NOT THE ONE
SHE'S MARRIED TO.
- SO YOU DON'T CRY
WHEN YOU TAKE THOSE OFF?
narrator:
HAVING FINALLY HAD SEX,
GOB CAN ADMIT HE NEVER
CONSUMMATED THEIR MARRIAGE.
- JUDGE, MAYBE YOU SHOULD TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
IT WAS TAKEN
IN YOUR OFFICE JUST MOMENTS AGO.
- BUT GOB CATCHES A LUCKY BREAK.
- THERE'S NO WAY TO TELL
WHO THIS MAN IS.
narrator:
BUT IT DOESN'T LAST LONG.
- THAT'S ME, YOUR HONOR.
I [bleep] MY WIFE.
- WELL,
WE REALLY LOST THIS CASE.
narrator: AND MAEBY IMPRESSES
THE KIDS AT THE PROMISED LAND
WITH HER ONE
SCARY CAMPFIRE STORY.
- KNOCK, SCRAPE.
THE ONLY THING
MORE TERRIFYING
THAN THE ESCAPED LUNATIC'S HOOK
WAS HIS TWISTED CALL!
- HEY, CAMPERS.
[kids Screaming]
- I'M A MONSTER!
- THIS MAY HAVE BEEN
A STEP BACKWARDS.
[waltzing music]
- [singing] UPON HER KNEE
SO FINE TO BE
MOTHER AND BOY
MOTHER
BOY