male narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING,
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL WAS SURPRISED
TO FIND THE HOUSE
STILL A MESS A WEEK
AFTER THE FUMIGATION.
- SO YOU STILL HAVEN'T PUT
THIS STUFF BACK YET, HUH?
YOU'VE GOT TO BE
THE LAZIEST PERSON IN THE WORLD.
- IF YOU WEREN'T ALL THE WAY
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE ROOM,
I'D SLAP YOUR FACE.
- I ASKED YOU TO CLEAN THIS UP.
- YEAH, AND YOU ALSO ASKED ME
TO CALL THE FUMIGATORS,
AND YOU HAVEN'T EVEN THANKED ME
FOR DOING THAT.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD ASKED HER
TO DO THIS,
BUT THAT WAS LONG BEFORE
HE BEGAN HIDING HIS FUGITIVE
FATHER IN THE ATTIC.
- WHAT? UH--OH, GOD.
POLLY, COVER YOUR MOUTH.
thunk!
narrator: LUCKILY, MICHAEL
WAS NOTIFIED IN TIME.
- WELL, WE HAD A DEAL, YOU KNOW.
I'D PAY FOR EVERYTHING,
AND YOU'D CLEAN THE HOUSE.
AND YOU'VE ONLY DONE IT ONCE.
narrator: SHE HADN'T
EVEN DONE IT THAT TIME,
BUT INSTEAD, INTERCEPTED
HER MOTHER'S HOUSEKEEPER
AS SHE WAS ARRIVING FOR WORK.
- CAN I TAKE YOU
THE REST OF THE WAY?
- MRS.-- MRS.--
- OH, I HAVE TO MAKE
ONE QUICK STOP FIRST.
- ALMOST DONE.
YOURS OR MISTER'S?
- MISTER'S.
narrator: LUPE NEVER ACCEPTED
A RIDE FROM LINDSAY AGAIN.
- WELL, I'M SORRY, MICHAEL,
BUT TOBIAS MOVING OUT
HASN'T BEEN EASY.
- FOR ANY OF US.
- YOU DIDN'T EVEN NOTICE
HE'D GONE, DID YOU?
- I DID NOTICE
WE'D STOPPED TIVOING
"THE CHRISTOPHER LOWELL SHOW."
WHAT HAPPENED?
- I TRIED TO GIVE IT
ONE LAST CHANCE.
LIKE WHAT YOU SEE?
- I'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR THOSE.
YOU'RE GONNA
STRETCH THEM OUT.
- THAT'S ALL YOU CAN SAY?
- WELL, EXCUSE ME FOR LIKING
THE WAY THEY SHAPE MY JUNK.
- I DON'T KNOW WHY,
BUT THAT'S IT.
YOU CAN PACK YOUR JUNK
AND GET OUT.
- YOU'RE KICKING ME OUT?
AT THE BEGINNING
OF PILOT SEASON?
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA MAKE IT
AS AN ACTOR,
AND WE'RE NOT
GONNA MAKE IT AS A COUPLE.
narrator: WITH NOWHERE TO GO,
TOBIAS WENT TO THE STUDIO
WHERE HE'D OCCASIONALLY WORKED
AS A SECURITY GUARD
AND TOOK UP RESIDENCE
IN THE APARTMENT OF DETECTIVE
FRANK WRENCH,
ON THE SET
OF THE TELEVISION SHOW,
"WRENCH."
- I'M REALLY SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
HOW'S MAEBY TAKING IT?
- WELL, SHE'S REALLY HARD
TO READ.
- YOU HAVEN'T TOLD HER YET.
- WELL, SHE WAS SO EXCITED
THE HOT WATER IN THE SHOWER
WAS LASTING LONGER,
HOW COULD I HAVE THE HEART
TO TELL HER IT'S BECAUSE
HER FATHER MOVED OUT?
- TOBIAS MOVED OUT?
DID HE TAKE THE GOOD
VIDEO CAMERA WITH HIM?
- THAT'S REALLY VERY TOUCHING,
GOB.
WHAT DO YOU NEED
THE CAMERA FOR?
- I'M MAKING A MAGIC VIDEO.
I'M GONNA TAPE MYSELF
DOING TRICKS AROUND THE OFFICE.
I'M CALLING IT "TRICKS"--
LET ME FINISH--
"AROUND THE OFFICE."
I FIGURED OUT A WAY TO
MAKE MONEY WHILE I'M WORKING.
- THAT IS WHAT WE CALL WORKING.
SOMETHING YOU MIGHT WANT TO TRY
NEXT TIME YOU'RE AT THE OFFICE.
YOU'VE BEEN MISSING THINGS
LATELY.
I'M GETTIN' REAL TIRED
OF IT.
INCIDENTALLY, TODAY WE'RE HAVING
A BIG VOTE
ON THAT BUILDING RENOVATION.
I NEED YOU THERE
TO HELP ME VOTE IT IN.
- FINE. I'LL VOTE
AT YOUR STUPID MEETING,
AS LONG AS
YOU GIVE ME THE CAMERA.
I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT GEORGE
MICHAEL WAS USING IT LAST.
narrator: A FACT THE FAMILY
HAD DISCOVERED
WHEN THEY'D GATHERED
TO WATCH A HOME VIDEO.
- WAS THAT
A 40th ANNIVERSARY PARTY, HUH?
DIDN'T COST US A THING.
- IS THAT QUSAY HUSSEIN
AT THE OMELET BAR?
- LOOK AT THIS. IF THESE GUYS
MOVE, THEY DON'T GET PAID.
narrator: IT SEEMS
THAT AS A 13-YEAR-OLD,
GEORGE MICHAEL HAD BEEN
HEAVILY INFLUENCED
BY THE STAR WARS FILMS
AND HAD ENDEAVORED TO
RE-CREATE HIS FAVORITE MOMENTS.
- YOU'RE NOT MY FATHER!
YOU'LL NEVER BE!
- I SPENT $2.1 MILLION
OF GOOD COMPANY MONEY
AND END UP WITH THIS?
- YOU CUT OFF MY HAND!
- WORTH EVERY PENNY.
EVEN YOU HAVE TO ADMIT
THAT THAT WAS THE LAMEST THING
EVER PUT ON TAPE.
narrator: NOT SO.
BUSTER HAD ONCE VIDEOTAPED
HIMSELF RE-CREATING MOMENTS
FROM HIS
THEN FAVORITE FILM, "CHICAGO."
- [trilling]
narrator:
HE ALSO LIKED STAR WARS.
- HOO-AH!
- HIS SELF-ESTEEM IS LOW ENOUGH
AS IT IS,
AND I HAVE NO IDEA WHY.
- I MEAN, HE'S SUCH A GREAT KID,
AND EVERYBODY LOVES HIM.
HE'S GEORGE MICHAEL.
TRUTHFULLY, THAT'S WHY I'M
NOT THAT CRAZY ABOUT THAT ANN,
BUT HE'LL MOVE ON.
- UNLESS HE KNOCKS HER UP
LIKE YOU DID WITH HIS MOTHER.
PLUS, SHE'S RELIGIOUS.
IF THAT ONE GETS PREGNANT,
IT STAYS PREGNANT.
BELIEVE ME. I DATED A CHICK LIKE
THAT ONCE IN HIGH SCHOOL.
NO, I DIDN'T.
- I GOT TO WORK
ON THAT BOY'S SELF-ESTEEM.
narrator: MICHAEL WENT TO DO SO,
ONLY TO HEAR ANN
BEATING HIM TO IT.
- I WANT YOU TO DO IT.
- I DON'T THINK I'M READY.
- OF COURSE YOU ARE.
- I'M GONNA LOSE IT
BEFORE I START.
- DON'T START!
SMOKING.
IT'S A KILLER.
THAT SAMMY DAVIS, JR.
SHOULD STILL BE PERFORMING.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- ANN THINKS I SHOULD RUN
FOR STUDENT BODY PRESIDENT.
- THAT IS A GREAT IDEA.
- WELL, I DON'T HAVE A CHANCE.
I MEAN, THEY ONLY VOTE
FOR THE COOL KIDS.
- BUT EVERYONE LOVES YOU.
- YOU ARE GEORGE MICHAEL.
WHO'S COOLER THAN YOU?
["Star Wars Main Theme"]
PLUS, YOU WOULD BE FOLLOWING
IN YOUR OLD MAN'S FOOTSTEPS.
- YOU WERE STUDENT BODY
PRESIDENT?
- OH-HO. IT WAS CLOSE.
- SO YOU LOST?
- WHO REMEMBERS?
- I KNOW I WOULD REMEMBER.
- ANN, IF MY DAD SAYS
THAT HE WON, THEN HE WON.
- DIDN'T SAY I WON.
SAID I CAN'T REMEMBER.
BUT NOW THAT WE'RE THINKING
ABOUT IT,
I SEEM TO REMEMBER THE OTHER GUY
WON THE ACTUAL TITLE,
ALTHOUGH THERE WERE PLENTY
IN THE SCHOOL
WHO WANTED
TO OVERTURN THE DECISION.
I SAID, "LET'S--DO NOT--
LET'S NOT PUT THE SCHOOL
THROUGH THAT."
HAVEN'T THOUGHT ABOUT THAT
FOR YEARS. GOOD MEMORY.
- WELL, ANYWAY, I'LL HELP YOU
RUN YOUR CAMPAIGN
AND MAKE YOUR COMMERCIAL
FOR ELECTION DAY.
- WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
THE IMPORTANT THING IS
TO RAISE THE OLD SELF-ESTEEM
AND NOT TO RUSH
A PHYSICAL RELATIONSHIP.
THOSE ARE REALLY
THE TWO IMPORTANT THINGS.
- OH, NO. WE'RE BOTH WAITING.
- GOOD.
- AND THEN THAT FIRST TIME,
AFTER WAITING AND WAITING,
IT'S GONNA BE SO AWESOME,
BECAUSE IT'S NOT JUST GONNA BE
MY LOVE AND GEORGE MICHAEL'S,
BUT GOD'S LOVE AS WELL.
GOD, IT'S GONNA BE INCREDIBLE.
- ALL RIGHT. I'LL DO IT.
I'M IN.
- CAMPAIGN?
- I'M PUMPED.
narrator: AS GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS ON THE PATH
TO HIGHER SELF-ESTEEM,
BUSTER WAS LOSING
WHAT LITTLE HE HAD.
- I CAN'T PUT THE AORTA IN
WITH THIS THING.
- OH, STOP COMPLAINING.
- BUSTER!
- I'M SORRY I'M AN INCONVENIENCE
TO YOU, MOTHER.
OH, GOD! OH, GOD!
OH!
[whimpering]
narrator: AS LUPE FELT SORRY
FOR BUSTER'S LOSS OF A HAND,
LINDSAY FELT SORRY
FOR HER LOSS OF LUPE.
[mystical Middle Eastern music]
LINDSAY HAD CLEANED ONE ROOM
AND NOW HAD A GARBAGE PROBLEM.
AND WHILE LOOKING FOR A SPOT
TO STASH THE REFUSE,
SHE CAME UPON AN OLD FRIEND.
- I HAVEN'T SEEN THIS
IN AGES.
EBAY.
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY, IT
WAS A NEW FRIEND TO GEORGE, SR.
- POLLY.
clank!
narrator:
AND BACK AT THE OFFICE,
MICHAEL CAME TO REGRET HAVING
GIVEN GOB THE VIDEO CAMERA.
- WELL, I CERTAINLY
APPRECIATE YOUR DECISION,
BUT IF MY BROTHER WAS HERE,
WE COULD'VE VOTED
THIS THING THROUGH.
- WHAT'S THIS?
A STUFFY OFFICE MEETING?
WELL, MAYBE IT'S TIME
FOR A LITTLE OFFICE MAGIC.
- WHAT'S "OFFICE MAGIC"?
- SOMETIMES IT'S AS SIMPLE
AS TURNING
10:45 IN THE MORNING INTO...
LUNCHTIME!
- WHY DOES LUNCH
HAVE TO BE SO DULL?
- MAYBE YOU'D
PREFER SOME CHICKEN INSTEAD!
- ALL RIGHT. LET'S CUT.
TAKE FIVE, EVERYBODY.
- NO, NO. WE'RE NOT TAKIN' FIVE.
HEY, IS THIS GUY WITH YOU?
- YEAH, HE'S AN ACTOR,
RON MICHAELSON.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
I THOUGHT HE WAS AN INVESTOR.
HE VOTED AGAINST ME,
WHICH IS THE VOTE I ASKED YOU
TO BE HERE FOR, SO--
YOU KNOW WHAT? I DON'T KNOW WHY,
BUT THAT'S IT.
OKAY, I DON'T THINK
I CAN WORK WITH YOU ANYMORE.
- WELL, YOU KIND OF HAVE TO,
GUY. I'M THE PRESIDENT.
- NO. I'M THE PRESIDENT.
- NO, YOU LOST THE PRESIDENCY.
JUST LIKE YOU DID IN HIGH SCHOOL
WHEN YOU REFUSED
TO PLAY DIRTY LIKE DAD
TOLD YOU TO; WORKED WHEN I RAN.
- WE'RE TALKIN'
ABOUT THE OFFICE HERE, OKAY?
I DO ALL THE WORK.
I'VE BEEN HELPING YOU.
BUT THAT'S OVER NOW.
- SORRY TO HEAR YOU SAY THAT,
MICHAEL,
'CAUSE IT JUST
COST YOU YOUR JOB.
- I'M SERIOUS. IT'S OVER.
- HOW DO YOU CALL SECURITY
ON THIS THING?
- YOU HIT POUND-ZERO-ZERO
TO OPERATE THE SYSTEM.
- POUND IS TIC-TAC-TOE, RIGHT?
- YEAH. POUND IS RIGHT--
- WHEN I KEEP HITTING THAT,
THE OTHER THING FLASHES.
- HIT POUND AND THEN ZERO-ZERO.
- I DO. I KNOW.
- TELL YOU WHAT, YOU DON'T NEED
TO LEARN THE SYSTEM,
BECAUSE YOU'RE OUT OF HERE.
- YOU'RE FIRED.
HAVE SECURITY SEND A MAN UP.
YOU'VE GOT THE WRONG GUY.
- UH, NO, YOU DON'T,
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THIS.
narrator: BUT THE GUARD
HAD RECENTLY LOST HALF HIS TIE
TO OFFICE MAGIC.
- OH, I DON'T MIND.
- GET THIS.
YOU GETTING THIS?
- CHEAT OUT. YOU HAVE
TO CHEAT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
- OH, HEY.
- WHAT WAS THAT ALL ABOUT?
- YOUR UNCLE DOESN'T
NOT WORK HERE ANYMORE.
SO I GUESS YOUR MOM TOLD YOU
ABOUT YOUR DAD MOVING OUT, HUH?
- NO, SHE DID NOT TELL ME THAT.
- OH.
- BUT SHE DOESN'T TELL ME
ANYTHING.
NEITHER OF THEM DO.
- SORRY. GUESS I SHOULDN'T
HAVE SAID ANYTHING.
- MAYBE I SHOULD JUST START
KEEPING SOME SECRETS OF MY OWN.
- WHY AREN'T YOU AT SCHOOL
RIGHT NOW?
- MARRY ME.
I'M SO SORRY.
I FORGOT WHO I WAS TALKING TO.
I WAS JUST USING YOUR COPIER
TO MAKE SOME CAMPAIGN POSTERS.
- WELL, THEN, BY ALL MEANS,
LET ME HELP YOU OUT.
- I MEAN, I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHY I'M DOING IT.
HE'S GONNA WIN BY A LANDSLIDE.
- THAT'S WHAT I WAS TELLIN' HIM.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW STEVE HOLT?
ARE YOU IN A.A.?
- I WAS TALKIN' ABOUT
GEORGE MICHAEL.
HE'S RUNNING
FOR STUDENT BODY PRESIDENT.
WHO'S STEVE HOLT?
- HE'S JUST THE HOTTEST GUY
IN SCHOOL.
AND HE'S WON
THREE YEARS IN A ROW--
EVERY YEAR
AFTER HIS FIRST JUNIOR YEAR.
- SO THEN HE'S MORE POPULAR
THAN GEORGE MICHAEL?
- WELL, THAT'S LIKE
COMPARING APPLES
AND SOME FRUIT
NOBODY'S EVER HEARD OF.
HE MIGHT EVEN FINISH
AFTER THE INDIAN KID.
- I GUESS I GOT TO GET DOWN
TO THE SCHOOL
AND SEE IF I CAN
STOP HIM FROM SIGNING UP, HUH?
- YES. YOU HAVE TO.
AND DO YOU THINK YOU
COULD PUT UP
A COUPLE
OF THESE WHEN YOU'RE THERE,
'CAUSE I WAS REALLY NOT
IN THE MOOD TO GO DOWN THERE.
narrator: MICHAEL WENT
TO TAKE CARE OF HIS SON,
AS LUCILLE DISCOVERED
THAT HERS
WAS ALREADY
BEING TAKEN CARE OF.
- [gasps] MOTHER!
- AND YET YOU'RE TOO GOOD
TO POLISH THE CANDLESTICKS?
YOU'RE FIRED!
- YOU CAN'T FIRE ME.
I'M YOUR SON.
I'M FIRING YOU!
- I WAS FIRING LUPE!
- WELL, THAT MAKES MORE SENSE.
- LINDSAY CAME UPON LUPE,
WHO'D JUST BEEN FIRED.
- CAN'T YOU AT LEAST COME OVER
AND DUSTBUSTER OR SOMETHING?
- I NO DOES BUSTER ANYMORE.
- FINE. I'LL DUSTBUSTER.
GOD.
- HELLO?
- HEY. I CAN'T TALK LOUDLY.
I'M IN THE BATHROOM
OF THE WRENCH SET,
AND THEY'VE STARTED SHOOTING.
ALSO, I DON'T THINK
THIS IS A REAL TOILET.
SO I JUST WANTED TO CHECK
ON MAEBY
AND TELL YOU THAT
I HAVEN'T LANDED A PART YET,
BUT DESPITE WHAT YOU MAY THINK,
MY TALENT SHALL WIN OUT.
- WELL, MAEBY'S FINE.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR A CLEANING LADY,
SO IF YOU HEAR OF ONE--
- SHH. SHH.
- SO FRANK WRENCH
IS GONNA CLEAN YOU.
WHY IS THIS DOOR LOCKED?
- CUT!
- IS SOMEBODY
USING THE SET BATHROOM?
- I GOT TO GO.
narrator: MICHAEL ARRIVED
AT SCHOOL
TO TALK HIS SON
OUT OF RUNNING FOR OFFICE.
- IT TOOK ME ALL DAY, BUT I GOT
THE 10 SIGNATURES.
I'M RUNNING
FOR STUDENT BODY PRESIDENT.
- LISTEN, GEORGE MICHAEL--
- WE'RE GONNA USE YOUR IDEA AND
REALLY HIGHLIGHT BEING CHASTE.
- WELL, I JUST MEANT
THAT YOU TWO SHOULDN'T--
HEY, YOU'RE NOT GONNA PUT UP
THIS POSTER, ARE YOU?
- THINK IT'S REALLY GONNA APPEAL
TO THE CHRISTIAN CROWD.
- YOU KNOW, I COULDN'T HAVE
DONE THIS WITHOUT YOU GUYS.
I'M GONNA WIN THIS THING.
all: [chanting] FOUR MORE YEARS!
FOUR MORE YEARS!
narrator: AND GOB SHOWED UP
AT HIS MOTHER'S.
- WELL, GUESS WHO'S BEEN FIRED.
- MICHAEL FIRED YOU?
- NO. I FIRED HIM.
BUT AS A RESULT, I'M NO LONGER
WELCOME IN THE OFFICE.
- WHAT A COINCIDENCE.
I JUST FIRED MY HOUSEKEEPER.
BUT I'VE
ALREADY FOUND A REPLACEMENT.
[machine whirring]
IT'S A ROBOT.
- I HATE IT.
I MISS LUPE.
- NO. I WON'T LET YOU
GO DOWN THAT ROAD.
I WANT YOU TO BE STRONG,
AND YOU DON'T NEED THE COMFORT
OF AN IMMIGRANT
IN MOTHER'S OLD STIRRUP PANTS
TO MAKE YOU FEEL THAT WAY.
- OH.
[beeping]
- OH, YOU'RE HUNGRY.
narrator: LINDSAY WAS ABOUT
TO FIND A REPLACEMENT
FOR LUPE AS WELL.
- WHO IS IT?
- THE NEW HOUSEKEEPER.
THE AGENCY SENT ME OVER.
- I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T CALL ANY--
- OH, ALLOW ME
TO INTRODUCE MYSELF.
MY NAME
IS PHYLLIDIA FEATHERBOTTOM,
AND I CAN COOK
AND I CAN CLEAN
AND I CAN
TAKE CARE OF THE LITTLE ONES.
I CAN ALSO SING A SONG OR TWO,
IF IT COMES IN HANDY.
[singing] WHEN YOU PUT A SQUIRT
OF FROSTING DOWN YOUR THROAT
BEFORE WE TAKE
OUR MEDICATIONS
narrator:
TOBIAS HAD GAINED ACCESS
TO THE STUDIO'S WARDROBE
AND MAKEUP DEPARTMENT.
HE WAS EAGER
TO BOTH SEE HIS DAUGHTER
AND PROVE TO HIS WIFE
THAT HE HAD WHAT IT TOOK
TO BE AN ACTOR.
IT WAS THE EXACT PLOT
OF THE FILM "MRS. DOUBTFIRE."
- [singing]
IN THE MOST DELICIOUS WAY
narrator: THERE WAS ALSO
SOME "MARY POPPINS" IN THERE.
- LET'S GET THIS
HOUSE CLEANED UP.
- HEY. LINDSAY,
THE PLACE LOOKS FANTASTIC.
WHAT? DID YOU PAY SOMEBODY
TO DO THIS?
- OH, I'VE NO NEED FOR PAYMENT.
THE LOVE OF THE FAMILY
IS MORE THAN ENOUGH.
- I'M SORRY.
THIS IS MRS. FEATHERBOTTOM.
- FROM BLACKSTOOL.
I'M CHARMED, I'M SURE.
OOH!
[giggling]
BACK TO WORK.
- I THINK HE MISSES
HIS DAUGHTER.
- THAT'S CONVENIENT,
CONSIDERING YOU DIDN'T EVEN
HAVE THE COURAGE
TO TELL MAEBY
THAT HE'D MOVED OUT.
- I'M SORRY. I'M NOT
THE PERFECT PARENT, LIKE YOU.
- I'M NOT THAT PERFECT.
I PUSHED GEORGE MICHAEL
INTO RUNNING FOR OFFICE,
AND I THINK HE'S GONNA GET
CRUSHED BY THIS KID STEVE HOLT.
- YEAH. I'D VOTE FOR STEVE.
TOO BAD DAD'S ON THE LAM.
YOU COULD FINALLY USE SOME
OF HIS DIRTY TRICKS
TO GET GEORGE MICHAEL ELECTED.
narrator: AS IT HAPPENS,
GEORGE, SR. HAD COME TO
IN THE ATTIC,
AND PERHAPS IT WAS THE EFFECT
OF LOSING HIS ONE FRIEND...
- POLLY?
narrator: OR THE LINGERING
EFFECTS OF THE FUMIGATION,
OR PERHAPS IT REALLY WAS
DIVINE INTERVENTION,
BUT HE'D HAD
A PROFOUND REALIZATION.
- [sniffs]
narrator: UNFORTUNATELY,
THE TIMING OF THE ENLIGHTENMENT
WASN'T IDEAL FOR MICHAEL.
- THAT'S WHY I NEED YOUR HELP,
POP.
- "OUR HEAVENLY FATHER
LET HIS SON DIE
SO THAT OUR SINS
COULD BE ABSOLVED."
- GREAT.
SO YOU'RE A CHRISTIAN NOW.
- "WE MUST ALL SEEK
FORGIVENESS."
- WELL, I'LL CALL THE WARDEN
FOR YOU.
YOU CAN ASK HIM YOURSELF.
- WELL, I THINK THAT'S
FOR FRESH CRIMES.
BESIDES, YOU'VE ALWAYS
TRIED TO LEAD A CLEAN LIFE.
YOU AND GOB WERE LIKE THOSE
BIBLICAL BROTHERS,
GALLANT AND, UM...
GOOFUTH.
narrator: MICHAEL REALIZED
HE HAD LIVED LIKE GALLANT,
AND IF HE WANTED
TO HELP HIS SON'S ELECTION,
HE WOULD HAVE
TO FIND GOOFUTH.
- BEEN LOOKIN' ALL OVER
FOR YOU, PAL.
- IF YOU CAME TO GROVEL
FOR THE JOB OF PRESIDENT,
YOU'RE TOO LATE.
MY BROTHER ALREADY FIRED ME.
- LISTEN, I'M REALLY SORRY
THAT I GOT UPSET WITH YOU,
YOU KNOW, AND I NEVER MEANT TO,
UM--
I DIDN'T EVEN MEAN TO FIRE YOU,
YOU KNOW?
I JUST GOT SO FRUSTRATED,
AND, GOB, YOU ARE MY BROTHER.
OF COURSE I'M GONNA
SUPPORT YOU.
- WELL,
NOW I FEEL BAD
FOR FIRING YOU.
- LISTEN, GEORGE MICHAEL
IS RUNNING
FOR STUDENT BODY PRESIDENT,
AND I HAVE A FEELING
HE'S GONNA GET SLAUGHTERED.
THE GUY HE'S RUNNING AGAINST
IS BASICALLY A YOUNG YOU.
- WOW. IT WON'T BE EASY
TO WIN A RACE AGAINST MYSELF.
OF COURSE,
IF ANYONE CAN DO IT, I CAN.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- I WISH I WAS 15 YEARS YOUNGER.
- NOW, HE DOESN'T NEED
TO BEAT HIM.
HE JUST NEEDS
TO BEAT THE INDIAN KID.
- IF I DO THIS,
YOU'LL REHIRE ME?
- OF COURSE I WILL.
- SEE, THE MERE FACT THAT
YOU THINK YOU CAN
SAYS TO ME
THAT I SHOULDN'T LET YOU.
COURSE,
WE BOTH NEED THE WORK.
[bowl clatters]
ROBOT'LL GET IT.
- WHERE THE HELL IS MY MAID?
ROBOT!
narrator: BUT THE ROBOT
WAS BUSY ELSEWHERE.
- [gasps]
[robot beeping]
[robot powers down]
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT, MOTHER?
I'M HALF MACHINE!
I'M A MONSTER!
[screaming and grunting]
narrator: MICHAEL BROUGHT GOB IN
TO CONSULT
ON HIS SON'S CAMPAIGN.
- FOCUS ON THE VIDEO AND SHY
AWAY FROM THE VIRGIN THING.
- OH, WE SHOULD
DEFINITELY SACRIFICE
THE WHOLE VIRGIN THING.
AND I GOT THE PERFECT WAY.
WE HAND OUT RUBBERS THAT SAY,
"WE SALUTE GEORGE MICHAEL."
WE'RE NOT EVEN SUPPOSED
TO HAVE OUTSIDE HELP.
- AND I DON'T WANT
TO MAKE STEVE LOOK BAD.
- YEAH, I JUST DON'T WANT MY SON
TO BE EMBARRASSED UP THERE,
SO LET'S NOT PLAY TOO DIRTY.
- UH, GOOD POINT, 2%.
- 2%, HUH? IS THAT
HOW LITTLE I LOST BY?
- LOST BY? THAT'S ALL YOU GOT.
- NOT REALLY IMPORTANT.
- YEAH, WELL, IF YOUR SON WANTS
MORE THAN 2%,
HE'S GONNA HAVE
TO GO AFTER STEVE HOLT.
SO I WANT YOU TO TELL ME
EVERY AWFUL RUMOR
YOU'VE EVER
HEARD ABOUT THIS KID.
- I CAN'T SUPPORT THIS,
AND NEITHER CAN
THE CHRISTIAN KIDS
THAT WERE GONNA
MAKE YOU PRESIDENT.
- UH--SHE'S--
ANN?
I THINK SHE'S REALLY UPSET
ABOUT THIS.
- SHE'LL FORGIVE YOU.
YOU'RE GEORGE MICHAEL.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
DOWNSTAIRS,
MAEBY WAS MEETING
HER NEW SINGING NANNY.
- NOW. TAKE YOUR FUN-FUN.
- THIS IS MY MOM'S,
AND IT'S FEN-PHEN, AND IT'S
BEEN BANNED BY THE F.D.A.
- OH! WELL.
[singing] YOU SHOULD ALWAYS
READ THE LABEL
YOU SHOULD ALWAYS
READ IT WELL
IN THE MOST DELICIOUS WAY
- MR. FINGERBOTTOM?
- MRS.
- RIGHT. MRS.
I SHOULD REALLY GET GOING.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO. SIT BACK.
WHAT'S THE RUSH? PLEASE.
I WANT TO HEAR ABOUT YOU.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
I'M SURE WHEREVER
YOUR FATHER IS RIGHT NOW,
SHE LOVES YOU VERY, VERY MUCH.
- NOT ENOUGH TO BE HONEST
WITH ME.
narrator: AND AFTER A FEW DAYS,
GOB WAS READY
TO UNVEIL
GEORGE MICHAEL'S NEW MESSAGE.
- DROUGHT, STARVATION--
THESE ARE THE THINGS MY FAMILY
HAS HAD
TO DEAL
WITH FOR GENERATIONS,
ALTHOUGH, FORTUNATELY, NOT SINCE
WE MOVED TO CORONA DEL MAR.
[scattered applause]
- GO HOME, YOU TERRORIST!
- HOW STUPID DO YOU HAVE TO BE
TO SAY SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
- YOU'RE NOT WANTED HERE!
- GOB.
- MICHAEL.
- YOU GOT GEORGE MICHAEL'S TAPE?
- YEAH. I GAVE IT
TO THE TECH GUY.
DON'T WORRY.
IT'S VERY TASTEFULLY DONE.
SURE YOU DIDN'T MAKE THAT VIDEO
IN A CAVE?
- NEXT UP,
PERENNIAL CANDIDATE STEVE HOLT!
narrator: AND SOON IT WAS TIME
FOR STEVE HOLT
TO PLAY HIS VIDEO,
WHICH HAD BEEN PRODUCED
BY HIS NEW CAMPAIGN MANAGER,
ANN VEAL.
- HI. I'M STEVE HOLT.
STEVE HOLT!
[cheering]
- THIS KID'S POPULAR?
LOOKS LIKE A CHICK I DID
ONCE IN HIGH SCHOOL.
GET A HAIRCUT!
- BUT RECENTLY,
I'VE BEEN DEALING
WITH THE FACT THAT
I'VE NEVER KNOWN MY FATHER,
BUT I FINALLY
FOUND A NEW FATHER.
YOU'RE PROBABLY WONDERING
WHAT THESE FOOTSTEPS ARE.
WELL, THIS IS MY SECOND TAKE.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A SECOND CHANCE AT MAKING GOOD.
[all cheering]
- YEAH. OKAY. WE NEED
TO PULL THE VIDEOTAPE.
- MY TAPE?
- WHY?
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
- narrator: BUT IT WAS TOO
LATE TO DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
- STEVE HOLT IS A BASTARD.
HE DOESN'T EVEN
KNOW WHO HIS REAL FATHER IS.
WHAT ELSE DON'T WE KNOW
ABOUT STEVE HOLT?
GEORGE MICHAEL BLUTH
IS A COOL GUY.
HIS DAD IS A POWERFUL EXECUTIVE
WORKING FOR THIS MAN.
THE GIRLS LIKE HIM JUST FINE.
YOUNG AND OLD.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
IN THE DARK.
- THAT'S WHY YOU HAD ME
DO THAT?
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
HAD NEVER BEEN MORE EMBARRASSED.
UNTIL THIS PART.
- UH-OH. I COULDN'T
FIND ANOTHER TAPE.
[kids laughing hysterically]
I LIKE STEVE'S MORE.
- GUESS I UNDERESTIMATED
THE RELIGIOUS VOTE.
SO STEVE WON?
- NO. STEVE DROPPED OUT
OF THE RACE.
HE SAYS HE WANTS
TO SPEND SOME TIME TRYING
TO FIND HIS REAL FATHER.
YOU KNOW, RAV NADIR, THE INDIAN
KID, HE GOT 97% OF THE VOTE.
- WELL, THAT LEAVES 3%.
YOU DID BETTER
THAN I DID WHEN I RAN.
- I TIED WITH BART SIMPSON
AND "SCHOOL SUCKS."
- I'M REALLY SORRY, BUDDY.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
I ONLY DID THIS
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT YOU
TO FEEL BAD ABOUT YOURSELF.
- HEY, IT'S STAR DORK.
- HEY, HE KNOWS YOU NOW.
I'M REALLY SORRY, BUDDY.
- IT'S JUST A DRAG.
I MEAN, I'M PRETTY SURE MY
GIRLFRIEND'S GONE FOREVER,
AND I NEVER WANTED
TO DO THIS IN THE FIRST PLACE.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
WAS THAT REALLY YOU
DOING THOSE LIGHTSABER MOVES?
YOU WERE INCREDIBLE.
- I'VE ONLY GOTTEN BETTER.
- YOU'RE STILL DOIN' THAT?
- SO YOU WANT
TO GRAB A CURTAIN ROD
AND GO OVER TO MY PLACE?
- WOW. I'D LOVE THAT.
THANKS, ANN.
YOU REALLY MAKE ME
FEEL GOOD ABOUT MYSELF.
- GOT TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT KID'S SELF-ESTEEM.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT..."
- YOO-HOO! I'LL TAKE YOU
THE REST OF THE WAY!
narrator: LUCILLE FINDS
A HOUSEKEEPER
THAT SHE WON'T LOSE HER SON TO.
- [singing] ALWAYS KEEP
FROM CRYING
EVEN THOUGH YOUR HEART
IS DYING
[both crying]
narrator: AND STEVE HOLT FINALLY
TRACKS DOWN HIS REAL FATHER.
- I'VE BEEN WONDERIN'
MY WHOLE LIFE WHO HE IS--
A SCIENTIST,
A DOCTOR, A SENATOR?
- WELL, WE GOT SOME BAD NEWS.
- WOW. IS THAT WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN TO MY HAIR?