narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
narrator: MICHAEL BLUTH HAD JUST
BEEN STUNNED TO DISCOVER...
THAT A CONTRACT HIS COMPANY WAS
COUNTING ON WAS BEING CUT BACK.
- YOU INITIALLY TOLD US TO
DESIGN AND BUILD 22 HOMES.
NOW YOU'RE SAYING 18.
THAT DOESN'T GIVE US ENOUGH
CAPITAL TO COMPLETE THE JOB.
AND WE'VE ALREADY GOT
THE BLUEPRINTS DRAWN UP
AND EVERYTHING.
narrator: WELL, THAT PART WASN'T
TRUE. BUT THEY WOULD'VE.
[dial tone]
- THAT WAS A VERY
IMPORTANT PHONE CALL.
- I DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME,
MICHAEL.
TOBIAS IS ABOUT TO WALK IN HERE
ANY MINUTE ASKING FOR A JOB.
I NEED YOU TO HIRE HIM.
[ring, dial tone]
- HI. I'M SOR--
- LOOK, IT ISN'T MY IDEA,
IT'S HIS.
BUT I NEED A BREAK
FROM MRS. FEATHERBOTTOM.
narrator: SINCE MOVING OUT,
TOBIAS HAD BEEN PRETENDING
TO BE A BRITISH HOUSEKEEPER...
AS A WAY TO BE CLOSE TO HIS
FAMILY.
- [singing in falsetto]
narrator: HOWEVER, HIS DESIRE TO
NOW BE DISCOVERED AS HIMSELF
WAS BECOMING BOTHERSOME.
- CAN'T YOU JUST TELL HIM
YOU KNOW THAT HE'S MRS.
FEATHERBOTTOM?
- OH, NO. SHE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO
CAN HAND WASH MY DELICATES.
- YEAH, THE REAL TOBIAS
WOULDN'T DO THAT.
- WOULDN'T DO WHAT?
- BE MICHAEL'S ASSISTANT.
- WELL, THAT'S WHAT I CAME
DOWN HERE TO ASK ABOUT.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND ME
MORE THAN QUALIFIED.
- IT'S REALLY NOT THAT SIMPLE.
UH, YOU'D HAVE TO
SUBMIT A RESUME.
- BOOYAH!
- WOW. GOBIAS INDUSTRIES.
- GOBIAS.
- RIGHT.
I REMEMBER, YEAH.
- AS IN "GO BUY US
A CUP OF--"
- YOU KNOW WHAT,
LOOKS LIKE YOU MIGHT BE
A LITTLE TOO QUALIFIED.
- HANG ON. WHY DON'T YOU LET
YOUR NEW ASSISTANT
TAKE ALL THIS DOWN?
- WOW, YOU ARE GUNG HO.
- YOU'RE GETTING A NEW
ASSISTANT?
IS THIS BECAUSE THE ORDER
WAS CUT BACK?
- NO. BUT IF YOU ARE CONCERNED
ABOUT KEEPING YOUR JOB,
YOU MIGHT WANT TO FOCUS
ON KEEPING
UNWANTED VISITORS
OUT OF MY OFFICE.
- I HAVE RABIES, MICHAEL.
YOU KNOW THAT. TODAY WAS
DAY FOUR OF MY SHOTS.
narrator:
STARLA HAD BEEN BITTEN BY
A WELL-KNOWN
MUSIC PRODUCER'S GUARD DOG.
- MICHAEL, STARLA TOLD US
ABOUT THE CUTBACK.
YOU KNOW, A LOT OF OUR OVERHEAD
IS TIED UP IN THE FACT...
WE ARE ON THE TOP FLOOR
OF A VERY EXPENSIVE BUILDING.
IF WE MOVE
JUST ONE FLOOR LOWER--
- TED, EVERYTHING'S FINE.
I GOT IT ALL UNDER CONTROL,
AND NOBODY NEEDS TO MOVE.
- I'M SORRY. TED, IS IT?
- YES.
- TED. DID TED
MAKE AN APPOINTMENT?
- NO, I JUST WORK
DOWN THE HALL AND--
- NO.
- WELL, THEN, TED CAN GET
THE HELL OUT OF THIS OFFICE!
- I'M TALKING--
- YOU GET THE HELL OUT!
AND THAT'S HOW YOU
KEEP OUT UNWANTED VISITORS.
- THANK YOU.
- ALTHOUGH, IF I MAY, LET ME
TAKE OFF MY ASSISTANT SKIRT...
AND PUT ON MY BARBRA STREISAND
IN "THE PRINCE OF TIDES"
ASS-MASKING THERAPIST PANTSUIT.
- WHAT?
- THE REASON THAT YOU
CAN'T ACCEPT MY HELP...
IS THE SAME REASON YOU CAN'T
HEAR THAT GENTLEMAN'S IDEA--
BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO BE IN
TOTAL CONTROL OF EVERYTHING.
AND IT'S GOING TO MAKE
YOU SICK IF YOU CAN'T LET GO.
- HEY, I'M FINE.
- OH?
- OH! OOH!
- SEE? HE'S RIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT A CONTROL PROBLEM.
BUT I KNOW THIS EASTERN MEDICINE
STORE, ANCIENT CHINESE SECRET.
- both: ANCIENT CHINESE SECRET,
HUH?
- I SENT GOB THERE
FOR HIS MIGRAINES.
- IT'S JUST A CRAMP.
I'M FINE.
narrator:
IN FACT, GOB WAS AT
ANCIENT CHINESE SECRET
AT THAT MOMENT,
BUT NOT FOR A MIGRAINE.
- YEAH, I NEED A TEA TO
GIVE MY DINGLE LESS TINGLE.
ME QUICK, WANT SLOW.
WAIT, THAT'S INDIAN.
- TEA FOR DONG.
- [speaking native language]
- SWEET BLADE.
- IT'S THE SWORD OF DESTINY.
IT'S FULL OF ANCIENT MAGIC.
- OH, YEAH?
YOU INTO MAGIC?
STILL, WHERE'D
THE LIGHTER FLUID COME FROM?
SO, IS IT FOR SALE?
I COULD USE IT IN MY ACT.
- MAYBE.
SWORD OF DESTINY
HUNDREDS OF YEARS OLD.
COME WITH ANCIENT STORY
OF WARNING AND--
- YEAH, I MAKE UP MY OWN PATTER.
JUST RING IT UP
WITH THE DONG TEA.
narrator:
AND GOB CAUGHT UP WITH MICHAEL.
- MICHAEL.
BEEN LOOKIN' FOR YOU.
- LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR DRAGONS, IN THE FUTURE.
- I WOULDN'T MOCK THE SWORD OF
DESTINY, MICHAEL.
- CAREFUL WITH THAT, GOB.
- BLEEDING?
- NOPE.
YEAH, THAT'S BLOOD.
IT'LL GET BETTER
BEFORE THE SHOW.
THAT'S WHAT
I NEED YOU FOR, MICHAEL.
I CAN'T PERFORM MY ILLUSION
AT THE GOTHIC CASTLE
BECAUSE I'VE BEEN BANNED
FROM THE MAGICIANS' ALLIANCE.
I NEED YOU TO
REGISTER AS THE MAGICIAN,
AND I'M THE LOWLY ASSISTANT.
THEN WE GET ON THE STAGE,
AND YOU RAM THE SWORD OF DESTINY
INTO MY BELLY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- REALLY PICKED UP STEAM THERE
AT THE END, BUT I CAN'T.
I'VE GOTTA TEACH GEORGE MICHAEL
HOW TO DRIVE.
AND THEN I GOTTA
GET RIGHT BACK HERE, BECAUSE--
- MICHAEL, IF I MAKE
THIS COMEBACK,
I'LL BUY YOU 100 GEORGE MICHAELS
YOU CAN TEACH TO DRIVE!
- YOU'RE LOSING BLOOD,
AREN'T YOU?
- PROBABLY.
MY SOCKS ARE WET.
- SORRY.
- YOU'LL BE SORRY!
WAIT, THAT DOESN'T WORK
AFTER HIS LINE.
narrator: AND MICHAEL RUSHED
HOME TO TEACH HIS SON TO DRIVE.
- KNOCK, KNOCK. HEY, MAEBY.
GEORGE MICHAEL, READY TO DRIVE?
I DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
- GET ME BEHIND THAT WHEEL.
- OH, NO, YOU WILL
NOT BE BEHIND THE WHEEL.
YOU'LL OBSERVE ME WHILE I
DEMONSTRATE SOME THINGS, OKAY?
I'LL BE QUIZZING YOU TOO,
HOTSHOT.
I'M GONNA GO GRAB
THE VIDEO CAMERA.
AND THEN, SCHOOL'S IN.
- I'D SKIP.
- WELL, NO, I NEED TO LEARN.
YOU CAN'T GET AROUND ANYWHERE
WITHOUT A DRIVER'S LICENSE.
narrator: ACTUALLY, MAEBY
HAD RECEIVED A COMPANY CAR
FROM THE MOVIE STUDIO...
WHERE SHE WAS SECRETLY
POSING AS AN EXECUTIVE.
BUT CURRENTLY, GEORGE SR. WAS IN
THE ATTIC MAKING A VIDEOTAPE--
- THIS IS MY DEMAND.
narrator:
WHEN MICHAEL FOUND HIM.
- WHAT'S THE DEAL
WITH THE TURBAN?
- HUH? [chuckles]
PRETTY SMART, HUH?
AND-AND IT'S WARM TOO.
- GUESS THAT MAKES SENSE.
- OH, HEY, I HEARD ABOUT
THAT REDUCED ORDER.
THOSE BASTARDS.
THIS VIDEOTAPE
IS FOR OUR EMPLOYEES.
YOU TAKE THIS AND PLAY IT.
THIS WILL REASSURE THEM
THAT SOMEONE IS IN CHARGE.
- WELL, SOMEONE IS IN CHARGE,
DAD. I'M IN CHARGE.
I'VE NEVER
EVEN TAKEN A SICK DAY.
- NO, A REAL AUTHORITY.
MY PRESENCE NEEDS
TO BE, UH, REINSTATED.
narrator: HIS FIRST EFFORT AT
DOING SO HAD ALREADY FAILED.
- WHEN DO YOU START
BEING MY MOLE AT MY COMPANY?
- ACTUALLY, MICHAEL TURNED ME
DOWN FOR THE JOB.
- WHAT?
- SOMETHING TO DO WITH THEIR
HOUSING ORDER BEING CUT BACK.
- OH, MY GOD, THAT'S A HORRIBLE
SIGN-- OW! DAMN IT!
- I'M THE AUTHORITY,
SO I WILL SAVE THE COMPANY.
AND I SAY NO VIDEOTAPE.
OOH!
- OH, YOU OUGHTA TAKE A SICK
DAY.
GET OUT OF THAT OFFICE.
- DON'T COUNT ON IT, DAD.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL WAS FINALLY READY
TO MAKE HIS SON WATCH HIM DRIVE.
- ALL RIGHT, STAIR CAR BASICS.
IN ORDER TO GET THIS THING
UP TO A MINIMUM SPEED,
YOU GOTTA JAM ON THE GAS PEDAL
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE, OKAY?
BUT IN ORDER TO
SLOW THIS THING DOWN,
YOU GOTTA GET ALMOST IMMEDIATELY
BACK ON THE BRAKE PEDAL...
'CAUSE YOU GOT ABOUT
TWO TONS OF STAIRS BEHIND YOU.
WE'RE GONNA COVER THE HYDRAULIC
FLAPS AND THE RISER SYSTEM...
AFTER I TELL YOU THE BASICS
ABOUT HOW TO AVOID A HOP-ON.
BUT THE FIRST THING
WE'RE GONNA GO OVER--
OW!
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL DECIDED THAT PERHAPS
IT WAS TIME FOR A SICK DAY.
LET'S GO OVER THE ROUTE
TO THE HOSPITAL. OW!
- MY BABY IS SICK, BUT MOTHER
IS HERE TO NURSE YOU.
- WELL, NOW I'M A LITTLE SICKER.
- WELL, DON'T YOU WORRY
ABOUT WORK TODAY.
I AM READY AND WILLING
TO STEP UP AND TAKE OVER.
- YEAH, AND I'LL GET GEORGE
MICHAEL READY
FOR HIS DRIVING TEST.
- NO, NO, NO, I'M GONNA TEACH
HIM WHEN I GET OUT.
AND NO ONE'S TAKING OVER
FOR ME AT THE BLUTH COMPANY.
- MICHAEL, THIS IS WHAT WE
TALKED ABOUT.
I'M SURE THEY'LL DO
JUST FINE WITHOUT YOU.
- WELL, YOU'RE WRONG,
BECAUSE WE'RE IN CRISIS THERE.
THEY NEED TO KNOW THAT
I'M IN CHARGE AND I'M IN CON--
I'M PEEING.
AM I PEEING?
- I'M SORRY.
WE GAVE YOU A LITTLE
SOMETHING TO RELAX YOU.
IT MAY HAVE TAKEN THE TINGLE OUT
OF YOUR GENITALS.
- OH, NO. YOU'RE NOT
TAKING CARE OF MY SON.
- I'M SORRY TO SAY THIS,
BUT IT'S TOO LATE FOR ME
TO DO ANYTHING FOR YOUR SON.
- LET HIM KEEP TALKING.
- BECAUSE DR. STEIN HERE
HAS ALREADY BEEN ASSIGNED
TO HIS CASE.
YOU'RE LUCKY.
HE'S THE BEST.
- WELL, ONLY IN THE COUNTY.
BUT I'M CERTAINLY GOOD ENOUGH TO
TAKE OUT THAT APPENDIX OF YOURS.
- APPENDIX?
- I DON'T BUY IT.
COULD BE A HERNIA.
- OR IT COULD BE YOUR COLON.
I'D WANT TO GET IN THERE
AND FIND SOME ANSWERS.
- WELL, I AM THE BEST DOCTOR
IN THE STATE.
BUT IF YOU DON'T
TRUST MY DECISIONS--
- NO, NO, NO. NO.
YOU'RE THE DOCTOR.
YOU SEE,
HE'S THE AUTHORITY HERE.
WE NEED TO RESPECT HIM
JUST LIKE THE EMPLOYEES
AT THE BLUTH COMPANY
NEED TO RESPECT ME.
- OKAY, I'M GOING TO
PUT YOU ON THIS MACHINE
TO SLOW DOWN YOUR HEART RATE.
HOPEFULLY NOT TOO SLOW,
BECAUSE IT'S ALREADY
DANGEROUSLY SLOW AS IT IS.
[chuckles]
- WHATEVER YOU THINK, DOCTOR.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
GOB WAS STILL TRYING
TO ARRANGE
HIS COMEBACK IN MAGIC.
- SO I'D BE A MAGICIAN
AND YOU'D BE MY ASSISTANT?
- WELL, ON PAPER, YES.
BUT ONCE THE SHOW STARTS,
AND YOU RAM THAT SWORD
THROUGH MY BELLY,
PEOPLE WILL KNOW THAT
I'M THE ONE WHO BELONGS
BACK IN THE ALLIANCE.
THE KIND OF TRICK THAT I CAN PUT
ON A DVD, LIKE TONY WONDER DOES.
narrator: TONY WONDER HAD
STARTLED THE WORLD
BY BAKING
HIMSELF INTO A LOAF OF BREAD.
HE SOLD THE DVD'S OF IT
ON HIS WEB SITE,
WHICH MANY CLAIMED SUFFERED
DUE TO ITS POP-UP ADS.
- THANKS.
I'M FINALLY BEING TREATED LIKE A
REAL PERSON, NOT SOME DEFORMED--
- [screams] HOOK! FORGOT ABOUT
THAT THING, ELEPHANT MAN.
GONNA HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
SOMETHING TO DO
SO THAT PEOPLE CAN
LOOK AT YOU
WITHOUT WANTING
TO KILL THEMSELVES.
narrator: THAT NIGHT, GEORGE SR.
HEARD ABOUT MICHAEL'S ILLNESS.
- THE EMPLOYEES ARE GONNA PANIC.
THEY NEED TO KNOW THAT
SOMEONE'S IN CONTROL.
- AND HOW DO WE DO THAT?
- BOOYAH!
narrator:
AND AT THE GOTHIC CASTLE,
BUSTER HAD BEEN OUTFITTED WITH
A MECHANICAL HALLOWEEN HAND.
- WHOA!
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE
GOT SOME DIRTY EARS.
- WELL, YOU'RE NOT ON THE BANNED
LIST, SO YOU CAN GO ON AT 6:00.
- 6:00? LOOKS LIKE
YOU'LL BE MY OPENER.
- TONY WONDER!
- [screaming]
[screams]
[panting]
- YOU LIKE BREAD?
- YEAH.
- HAVE SOME.
- WOW, IT'S WARM.
- HOW DID YOU DO THAT?
- OH, HO, HO.
MAGICIANS ONLY.
[whispering] I FOLDED IT UP
INTO SOME SQUARES,
AND I PUT IT
IN A POUCH UNDER MY SHIRT,
AND THEN I PULL IT OUT,
AND I MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
IT CAME OUT OF MY SKIN.
- WOW, THAT SOUNDS EASY.
- KEEP IT TO YOURSELF.
AND GOOD LUCK UP THERE
TONIGHT.
AND YOU!
YOU'LL GET THERE SOMEDAY.
I STARTED OUT AS A LITTLE "W."
SOMEHOW I BECAME A BIG ONE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW
IT HAPPENED. ALL RIGHT?
[screaming]
MY EYE!
[screams]
[panting]
ENJOY THE HANUKKAH
COOKIE, MAN.
- WHAT A COOL GUY.
narrator: TOBIAS HAD BEEN SENT
TO THE OFFICE BY GEORGE SR.
- MY NAME IS DR. TOBIAS FUNKE
AND I'LL BE FILLING IN
FOR MICHAEL, WHO IS NOT SICK.
[chuckles]
IN FACT, JUST TODAY I SAW
A SLIVER OF HIS BUTTOCKS,
AND THEY'RE AS FRESH AND FIRM
AS A GEORGIA PEACH,
SO NOT TO WORRY.
BUT BEFORE YOU ALL RISE UP
AND SAY,
"WELL, LET'S MAKE
THIS MAN OUR LEADER,"
WELL, I THINK THAT WON'T BE
NECESSARY AFTER YOU SEE THIS.
IS THIS RIGHT?
narrator:
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY HAD ALSO
VIOLATED MICHAEL'S AUTHORITY..
AND WAS TEACHING
GEORGE MICHAEL TO DRIVE.
- ARE YOU SURE YOU DON'T WANT ME
TO JUST WATCH YOU FOR A WHILE?
- DRIVING IS ABOUT CONFIDENCE,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
JAM ON IT!
IT FEELS GREAT, RIGHT?
NOW, PUT YOUR FOOT ON THE BRAKE.
THERE'S A LIGHT IN A HALF MILE.
[brakes grinding]
narrator: MEANWHILE, BUSTER
AND GOB HAD BEGUN...
THE SWORD OF DESTINY ILLUSION
AT THE GOTHIC CASTLE.
[hand whirring]
- AH-AH, AH-AH, AH-AH!
OOH! WHOO!
- STOP IT, BUSTER.
- AND NOW OUR MAGIC TRICK.
- ILLUSION.
- SILENCE, SLAVE!
IN THIS MAGIC TRICK,
I'M GOING TO PUT A SWORD...
THROUGH MY ASSISTANT'S TUMMY.
- NO PATTER.
- MAY I HAVE THE TRICK SWORD,
PLEASE?
- IT'S A REAL SWORD,
MASTER.
- OH-HO!
[light applause]
[applause increases]
- OOH! HOO, HOO, HOO!
- WE'VE GOT 'EM. I'M GONNA MILK
THIS FOR A MINUTE.
- OKAY.
- [panting]
- [applause]
- [whooping]
- [screaming]
MY HAND! MY HAND!
[motor whirring]
narrator: AND THE AUDIENCE
WASN'T THE ONLY ONE IMPRESSED
BY THE PERFORMANCE.
- BRAVO.
HEY, GIVE US A SEC,
WOULD YOU, CANDIDA?
MY BROTHER'S WIDOW.
IT'S-- [bleep] UP.
HEY, SO THE ACCIDENT ANGLE.
RIGHT ON.
- OH, THANK YOU,
VERY MUCH.
- NO, THANK YOU.
THE "HOW'D HE DO DATS?"
ATE IT UP.
SORRY. THAT'S WHAT
WE CALL THE AUDIENCE.
- NO, I-I KNOW--
I KNOW ABOUT ALL THAT.
USED TO HAVE A SOLO ACT.
THERE WAS TALK OF BOILING ME
INTO A BISQUE AT ONE POINT.
- NOT REGISTERING.
BUT YOU HITCHED YOUR WAGON
TO THE RIGHT STAR.
I WANT YOU GUYS ON MY NEXT DVD.
- YOU WANT US FOR
"USE YOUR ILLUSION?"
- WELL, ACTUALLY, SOME BAND HAS
GOT THE RIGHTS TO THAT TITLE.
SO, I'M THINKIN', LIKE,
USE YOUR ILLUSION II.
BUT, YEAH,
MEET ME OUT THERE TOMORROW.
AND, UH, IF YOU GET THIRSTY--
[screaming]
HAVE A FREE ROUND OF DRINKS,
COURTESY OF TONY WONDER.
- IT'S A SUBWAY SUB
CLUB CARD.
- THAT'S A MAGICIAN.
- OH, IT STILL NEEDS
THREE STAMPS.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST COME
AROUND FROM HIS APPENDECTOMY.
- GIVE ME THE PHONE.
I WANT TO CALL GEORGE MICHAEL,
TELL HIM I'M OKAY.
- HE'S ON HIS WAY HERE.
WE PASSED HIM ON THE ROAD.
HE WAS DOING REALLY WELL.
HAD HIS FIRST HOP-ON.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
HE'S DRIVING? I TOLD LINDSAY
NOT TO TEACH HIM.
I WAS GOING TO
VIDEOTAPE THAT HOP-ON.
- HEY, DAD.
HOW'RE YOU FEELING?
- BAD, GEORGE MICHAEL.
I JUST FOUND OUT LINDSAY'S
TEACHING YOU HOW TO DRIVE.
- YEAH. SHE'S STILL TRYING TO
GET THE STAIRS UNWEDGED
FROM THE EMERGENCY ROOM
OVERHANG.
- I WAS GONNA TEACH YOU.
YOU KNOW THAT.
JUST FORGET EVERYTHING SHE TOLD
YOU, AND WE'LL START OVER.
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
TOBIAS IS RIGHT.
- WHAT?
- YOU HAVE TO CONTROL
EVERYONE'S LIFE.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE YOU
GET THAT FROM.
OSCAR,
STOP LICKING THAT SORE.
- I'M NOT.
- WELL, THE OPERATION WENT
PRETTY SMOOTHLY.
BUT ONCE I GOT IN THERE,
THE APPENDIX WASN'T SO INFLAMED.
D'OH.
- I KNEW IT.
- OKAY. WELL, CAN WE
GET ME OUT OF HERE?
I GOTTA RETRAIN MY SON
HOW TO DRIVE,
AND I NEED TO
STOP BY THE OFFICE...
TO MAKE SURE MY BUSINESS
DOESN'T GO TO HELL.
- AND, NOT SO FAST, MICHAEL.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A BACTERIAL
INFECTION FROM THE OPERATION...
WHICH LEFT AN ABSCESS
IN YOUR ABDOMINAL WALL.
- EW.
- I KNOW, IT'S PRETTY GROSS.
BUT IT COULD HEAL ON ITS OWN.
BUT I SAY WE GO IN THERE
DR. STEIN-STYLE AND CUT IT OUT.
I WANT TO SHOW THESE INTERNS
WHAT THE BEST DOCTOR
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA CAN DO.
- WELL, I RESPECT YOUR DECISION.
- I'LL CHECK ON YOU SOON.
- MICHAEL, THIS CRAZY POINT
YOU'RE TRYING TO MAKE ABOUT
RESPECTING AUTHORITY IS ABSURD.
AND ONE DAY, YOU'RE GONNA
WAKE UP
AND FIND OUT IT HAS
CAUSED YOU NOTHING BUT TROUBLE.
- AND YOU ARE PEEING AGAIN.
narrator: AND AS
THE ANESTHESIA TOOK HOLD,
MICHAEL REALIZED HE WAS GOING TO
WAKE UP TO NOTHING BUT TROUBLE.
announcer: THE F.B.I. HAS
PINPOINTED THE LOCATION
OF ESCAPED CONVICT
GEORGE BLUTH TODAY,
THANKS TO A TAPE TURNED IN BY A
RABID AND DISGRUNTLED EMPLOYEE.
THE F.B.I. HAS MATCHED THE
DESIGN OF THE ATTIC
TO ONE OF
SADDAM HUSSEIN'S IRAQI HOUSES.
AND IT APPEARS
HIS SON IS WITH HIM.
- THIS IS MY DEMAND.
- BOOYAH!
narrator:
BUSTER AND GOB WERE WAITING
TO MEET WITH TONY WONDER.
- ALL RIGHT.
HE'S GONNA LOWBALL US,
SO JUST LET ME DO
THE TALKING, ALL RIGHT, BUSTY?
THIS DVD IS THE DESTINY
THE SWORD HAS CHOSEN FOR ME.
- I WONDER WHERE HE IS.
- DID SOMEBODY SAY, "WONDER"?
- HE JUST APPEARED OUT OF
NOWHERE,
IN FRONT OF THAT DUMBWAITER.
narrator: ACTUALLY, HE'D BEEN
HIDING INSIDE THE DUMBWAITER
FOR OVER 20 MINUTES,
WAITING FOR SOMEONE
TO USE THE WORD "WONDER."
- I WONDER WHERE HE IS.
OH, HEY, YOU'VE GOT A PIECE OF
LETTUCE ON YOUR SHOULDER.
- TA-DA!
PART OF THE TRICK.
SO, LET'S GET DOWN
TO BUSINESS, SHALL WE?
HEY, CAN YOU, UH, GO WAIT WITH
THE OTHER ASSISTANTS OVER THERE?
- WHAT?
- NO, WHATEVER YOU SAY TO ME,
YOU CAN SAY TO HIM.
I GRANT HIM MAGIC SANCTUARY.
- UH, YOU GRANT ME? COME ON,
YOU CAN'T JUST MAKE UP--
- THAT'S FINE.
I SECOND THE SANCTUARY,
BUT WITH A CLAUSE OF SILENCE.
SO, I WANT YOU GUYS TO BE ON
USE YOUR ILLUSION.
ONLY NOW
IT'S "ALLUSION" WITH AN "A."
SO IF YOU GUYS WANT TO PUT AN
ALLUSION IN THERE SOMEWHERE,
LIKE, YOU KNOW, POE OR
SOMETHING OR--
DON'T DO POE,
'CAUSE I'M DOIN' POE.
- WHAT ABOUT CHAUCER?
- JUST NOT POE, OKAY?
AND, UH, I DON'T THINK
WE NEED, UH, YOUR ASSISTANT.
- WHAT?
- EH! CLAUSE OF SILENCE.
LOOK, MY ASSISTANT
IS MY PARTNER. I NEED HIM.
- FOR WHAT, BUSTER, HUH?
YOU'RE THE MAGIC.
CHECK OUT THOSE MOVES
YOU'RE DOIN', MAN.
THEY'RE IN THEIR OWN ORBIT.
LOOK AT TIAGRA, MY GIRL.
DON'T LOOK AT HER.
'CAUSE YOU LOOK AT HER AND
IT AFFECTS HER IN A WAY THAT
I DON'T FEEL COMFORTABLE WITH.
OR GO FOR IT.
I DON'T CARE, WHATEVER.
I'M JUST SAYIN' IT'S YOUR WORLD.
- ALL RIGHT, YOU KNOW WHAT?
THE TRICK IS ON YOU,
TONY WONDER.
I'M THE MAGICIAN.
HE'S THE ASSISTANT.
WE DON'T NEED HIM!
THE REAL SWORD OF DESTINY TRICK
HASN'T EVEN BEEN PERFORMED YET.
TA-DA!
- WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA. WAIT.
ARE YOU TELLIN' ME THAT
YOU HAVE A MULTI-STAGE TRICK
WITH HIDDEN IDENTITIES?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
AND I'M GONNA PERFORM
THE REAL TRICK THIS AFTERNOON.
- I GUESS WE'LL SEE
WHAT YOU CAN DO THEN.
- I GUESS WE WILL.
- [screaming]
OW! DARRYL,
I TOLD YOU TO MOVE THAT--
[bleep] CHAIR 10 TIMES!
AND CLEAN THE-- [bleeps]
DUMBWAITER WHILE YOU'RE AT IT!
- OH, I WAS REALLY HOPING
FOR A GRAHAM CRACKER.
- THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN
A GOOD SPOT FOR A TRICK.
narrator: MICHAEL AWOKE
FROM HIS SECOND SURGERY.
- MORNING, SLEEPYHEAD.
- DID YOU GET THE ABSCESS?
- WELL, UH, WE HAD
A LITTLE WHOOPSIE.
SEE, WE GOT THE ABSCESS,
BUT I THINK WE MIGHT HAVE LEFT
SOME SNIPPERS IN THERE.
IT'S NOT VERY LIKELY,
BUT ONE OF THE ASSISTANTS HAVING
TAKEN THEM IS EVEN LESS LIKELY.
UNLESS I LEFT THEM
IN MY SCRUBS.
- MICHAEL, GOOD NEWS.
THEY THINK GEORGE IS IN IRAQ.
ALL THE PRESSURE'S OFF HIM.
- THAT WAS ON THE NEWS?
I THOUGHT THAT I DREAMT THAT.
OH, THEY'RE GONNA THINK
THAT I'M THERE. OW!
- BUT NOT TO WORRY.
TOBIAS SAID HE'S HANDLING IT
WITH THE F.B.I.,
AND THE EMPLOYEES
HAVE EVERYTHING UNDER CONTROL.
- NO, THAT'S THE WORST THING
POSSIBLE.
THEY THINK THE COMPANY'S IN
TROUBLE AND THAT I'M IN IRAQ.
I GOTTA GET DOWN THERE.
I NEED YOUR CAR KEYS.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL AND
GEORGE MICHAEL
HEADED TO THE OFFICE.
- RIGHT HERE, GENTLEMEN.
narrator: WHICH IS HOW
TOBIAS MISSED HIM.
- MICHAEL BLUTH IS NOT...
IN IRAQ.
MICHAEL, BACK TO BED WITH YOU.
YOU LOOK AWFUL.
narrator: MICHAEL RUSHED TO
THE OFFICE
ONLY TO FIND THAT
HIS WORST FEARS HAD COME TRUE.
- WE'RE TOO LATE.
IT'S GONE.
EVERYBODY SAID THAT
I WAS TOO CONTROLLING,
BUT I WALK AWAY FOR ONE MINUTE,
LOOK WHAT HAPPENS
TO THE COMPANY.
I MEAN, THIS IS WHY
I DIDN'T WANT-- DAMN IT!
- DAD, YOU SHOULD
PROBABLY TAKE IT EASY.
- I SAID THAT THIS WOULD HAPPEN,
DIDN'T I?
I SAID RESPECT MY AUTHORITY,
BUT NO ONE WOULD LISTEN.
EVERYBODY HAD
THEIR OWN BETTER ID-- OW!
narrator:
AND MAYBE IT WAS THE STRESS
OR EVEN THE MISPLACED SNIPPERS,
BUT MICHAEL
HAD NEVER FELT WORSE.
HOWEVER, THANKS TO TAKING ON
HIS AUTHORITY,
THE EMPLOYEES
HAD NEVER FELT BETTER.
- TED?
- OH, HEY, MICHAEL.
GOOD NEWS.
WE LEASED THE TOP FLOOR
TO ANOTHER COMPANY
AND MOVED DOWN HERE.
BUT WE CAN STAY IN BUSINESS
WITHOUT HAVING TO BUILD
THE EXTRA HOUSES.
WE DID IT.
WE DID IT!
[cheering, applause]
- YOU'RE GOIN' DOWN,
RIGHT?
- WHOO!
narrator: AND BACK AT THE GOTHIC
CASTLE,
GOB WAS PERFORMING HIS ILLUSION.
- HEY, AFTER I CUT THE CANDLE IN
HALF,
SWITCH OUT THE REAL SWORD
FOR THE FAKE ONE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
I'M GOB BLUTH.
I'M THE REAL MAGICIAN.
THIS MAN IS ONLY THE ASSISTANT.
[audience gasps]
BUSTER, THE SWORD.
HANDLE FIRST.
HANDLE FIRST. [screams]
- [gasping]
- OH, MY FINGERS!
HE CUT OFF MY--
[bleep] FINGERS!
- [whimpers] OH!
- NO!
[applause]
[Gob moaning]
- GUY IS GOOD. DAMN GOOD.
- BRAVO!
- I'M NOT KIDDING!
HE CUT OFF MY--[bleep] FINGERS!
- I DIDN'T KNOW WE HAD TAQUITOS.
- MORE! MORE!
narrator:
AND MICHAEL CAME TO A DECISION.
- YOU KNOW WHAT,
GEORGE MICHAEL?
I THINK I'M GOING TO GIVE UP
SOME OF MY AUTHORITY,
STARTING NOW.
YOU DRIVE HOME.
ALL RIGHT?
narrator:
UNFORTUNATELY, MICHAEL'S
DECISION TO LET HIS SON
DRIVE A CAR
WITH A MORE RESPONSIVE
GAS PEDAL...
- [groans]
narrator: WAS NOT A GOOD
DECISION.
- YOUR LEG'S GONNA BE
FINE, MICHAEL.
AND I WOULDN'T WORRY ABOUT
GETTING HIT BY ANY MORE CARS.
I'VE SHORTENED YOUR CALF
MUSCLES
TO THEORETICALLY
INCREASE YOUR JUMPING ABILITY.
BUT IF IT WORKS, I COULD BE
THE BEST IN THE WORLD.
- I WANT THE OTHER DOCTOR BACK.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL GETS A NEW ROOMMATE.
- YOUR FINGERS HAVE BEEN
PERFECTLY REATTACHED.
GO AHEAD, TAKE A LOOK.
- MY MIDDLE FINGER
AND INDEX FINGER ARE--
- SWITCHED FOR
THE FIRST TIME EVER.
- NICE JOB, FRANK.
- AMAZING.
narrator: AND THE F.B.I.
FINDS FOOTAGE MORE TROUBLESOME
THAN THEY'D ORIGINALLY THOUGHT.
- IT APPEARS THERE WAS SOMETHING
ELSE ON THE VIDEOTAPE.
WE THINK IT'S A TERRORIST
TRAINING FILM.
- YOU'RE NOT HALF
THE MAN HE WAS!
[muffled shouting]
- THIS KID'S GOT MOVES.