male narrator:
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
narrator:
MICHAEL CAME HOME
TO FIND HIS BROTHER-IN-LAW,
TOBIAS,
WHO'D BEEN KICKED OUT OF
THE HOUSE EARLIER THAT WEEK.
- HOW ARE YOU?
- I'M GOOD.
DIDN'T I ALREADY SEE YOU TODAY?
- NOT THAT I KNOW OF.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD
SEEN HIM EARLIER THAT DAY,
AS TOBIAS HAD BEEN POSING
AS AN ENGLISH NANNY,
NAMED MRS. FEATHERBOTTOM.
- WHO'D LIKE
"A BANGER IN THE MOUTH"?
OH! RIGHT! I FORGOT.
HERE IN THE STATES,
YOU CALL IT
"A SAUSAGE IN THE MOUTH."
- WE JUST CALL IT "SAUSAGE."
narrator: THE FAMILY, OF COURSE,
KNEW IT WAS TOBIAS,
BUT THE HOUSE
HAD NEVER BEEN CLEANER.
- HELLO, YOUNG LADY.
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU IN A WEEK.
- OH. RIGHT.
THAT MEANS MRS. FEATHERBOTTOM
ISN'T HERE,
WHICH MEANS
SHE DIDN'T IRON MY BLOUSE,
WHICH MEANS I DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING TO WEAR
FOR MY PREMIERE.
THE PREMIER...OF CANADA.
HE'S GOING OUT
WITH MY GYM TEACHER.
narrator: MAEBY WAS ACTUALLY
REFERRING TO
THE PREMIERE OF A FILM
FROM THE STUDIO
WHERE SHE HAD CONNED HER WAY
INTO A JOB
- OH, HEY. JACK.
DID YOU EVER GET A CHANCE
TO DO THAT COVERAGE ON
"VOICES IN AMERICA:
HISTORY AND PERSPECTIVE?"
- YEAH, I LOOKED THAT UP.
IT'S A NINTH-GRADE
HISTORY TEXTBOOK.
- YEAH, AND IF I DON'T
GET YOUR REPORT ON IT,
I WON'T BE ABLE TO PASS...
ON IT.
BECAUSE I HAVE A FEELING
IT'S A PIECE OF [bleep].
narrator:
UNFORTUNATELY, THE JOB
WAS WREAKING HAVOC
WITH HER LANGUAGE.
- MAYBE WE JUST NEED
A NEW [bleep] HOUSEKEEPER.
- OKAY.
I'M SURE SHE WOULD HAVE
IRONED IT FOR YOU
HAD YOU TOLD HER ABOUT IT
BEFORE SHE CHANGED OUT OF
HER BLOODY WORK CLOTHES.
BUT I AM OFF THEN.
- WELL, I GOT
TO KEEP HIM TRYING,
AND THAT IS THE JOB.
- MICHAEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING TOMORROW?
- HAVING MY DAY RUINED
WITH WHATEVER
YOU'RE ABOUT TO ASK ME TO DO.
- IT'S MY WEDDING ANNIVERSARY.
AND OSCAR WANTS
TO THROW ME A PARTY.
- HE IS AWARE THAT HE'S NOT
MARRIED TO YOU, RIGHT?
narrator: IN FACT,
OSCAR HAD STARTED TO PERCEIVE
THAT LUCILLE
WAS PULLING AWAY FROM HIM.
- NOT NOW.
IT'S MY TIME OF THE MONTH.
[inhales sharply]
NOT NOW.
I DON'T WANT TO RISK
HAVING A BABY.
IT COULD KILL ME.
narrator:
SO HE WENT TO BUSTER FOR ADVICE
- I THINK SHE MISSES MY BROTHER.
- MY FATHER?
- YES?
I MEAN, YES.
MAYBE I SHOULD THROW HER
AN ANNIVERSARY PARTY.
- [gasps]
OH!
SO WHEN HE DOESN'T SHOW,
SHE'LL REALIZE THAT
YOU WERE THE ONE
WHO WAS ALWAYS THERE FOR US.
- WELL, I-I WAS THINKING
ONE MORE PARTY
AND THEN I'D MOVE OUT,
BUT--NO.
I-I LIKE YOUR PLAN BETTER.
THE ONLY PROBLEM IS
WE KNOW H-HE'S AROUND SOMEWHERE.
- WELL, HE NEVER RETURNED
WHEN I LOST MY HAND.
BUT YOU,
YOU NOT ONLY EMBRACE IT,
BUT I SAW YOU KISSING IT WHILE
YOU THOUGHT I WAS SLEEPING.
[giggles]
[man singing]
BAH-BAH-DAH-BAH
MMM
OKAY
- WHO KNOWS WHAT GOES ON IN
THAT POT-ADDLED MIND OF HIS.
ANYWAY, IT'S A PARTY,
AND I WANT
THE WHOLE FAMILY THERE.
- WE'RE HAVIN' A PARTY?
- NO.
WELL, I'M SORRY IF I DON'T WANT
YOU DOING ONE OF
YOUR STUPID PUPPET SHOWS.
- I DID THAT ONCE, MOM.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
THOUGHT IT WAS PRETTY COOL.
narrator:
IN AN EFFORT TO HIP UP HIS ACT,
GOB HAD BRIEFLY
INTRODUCED A PUPPET.
- CAN I TELL YOU
SOMETHIN', MY MAN?
SURE, FRANKLIN.
YOU ARE ONE COOL [bleep].
SPEAKIN' OF MOTHERS,
LET ME GIVE THAT OATMEAL
SOME BROWN SUGAR.
- GET OFF MY WIFE, YOU BASTARD!
- OH, MAN.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
FRANKLIN SAID SOME THINGS WHITEY
JUST WASN'T READY TO HEAR.
- GOB, WEREN'T YOU ALSO
MERCILESSLY BEATEN OUTSIDE OF
A CLUB IN TORRANCE FOR THAT ACT?
- HE ALSO SAID SOME THINGS
THAT AFRICAN-AMERICANY
WASN'T READY TO HEAR EITHER.
- YOU KNOW, MOM,
WE HAVE NO IDEA WHERE DAD IS.
HOW'S HE GONNA
HEAR ABOUT THE PARTY?
- WHY DO YOU HAVE
THE BABY MONITOR OUT?
- I'M, UH, LISTENING IN--
- SHE WANTS HER MAN BACK.
- ON MY SON.
- YO, MAN.
YOU'RE GONNA GET YOUR
SORRY WHITE ASS THROWN IN JAIL.
I SAID THAT'S ENOUGH.
narrator:
MICHAEL CAME UP
WITH AN EXCUSE HE KNEW
HIS MOTHER WOULD UNDERSTAND.
- I'M LISTENING IN ON MY SON.
I'M A LITTLE WORRIED
ABOUT HIS GIRLFRIEND, ANN.
- MY ADVICE,
GET ONE OF THOSE TEDDY BEARS
WITH THE CAMERAS IN THEM.
I HAD ONE IN BUSTER'S ROOM
TO MAKE SURE HE WASN'T GETTING
TOO SERIOUS WITH ANYONE.
AS IT TURNED OUT,
HE GOT TOO SERIOUS
WITH THE TEDDY BEAR.
I'LL SEE YOU
AT THE ANNIVERSARY PARTY.
- GANGY'S HAVING
AN ANNIVERSARY PARTY?
- SEEMS THAT WAY.
- HEY, IS FRANKLIN
GONNA BE THERE?
- SEE THAT, MIKE?
KIDS LOVE FRANKLIN.
- I JUST DON'T WANT HIM
TO POINT OUT MY CRACKER ASS
IN FRONT OF ANN.
- OH...
IMAGINE WHAT HE'D SAY
ABOUT HER.
- SO YOU WERE LISTENING IN
ON GEORGE MICHAEL.
CAN YOU BELIEVE WHAT HE ASKED ME
THIS MORNING?
- HEY, DO YOU THINK
MY MOM'S ENGAGEMENT RING
IS STILL AROUND?
- OF COURSE IT IS.
YOUR FATHER WOULD NEVER PART
WITH SOMETHING SO PRECIOUS.
narrator: IN FACT, LINDSAY
WAS CURRENTLY WEARING IT
ON HER MIDDLE TOE, ROAST BEEF.
- YOU KNOW, I'M THINKING OF
ASKING ANN TO GET PRE-ENGAGED.
-YOU ARE?
- YEAH.
WELL, I FEEL LIKE GOD MOVED HER
HERE FROM OHIO
JUST TO BE WITH ME.
- HER?
- WELL, THAT'S THE FIRST
I'VE HEARD OF THIS.
- WELL, THEN WHO SAID, "HER?"
- ME. THAT WAS--
THAT WAS ME.
BUT, UM, HER?
- LOOK, IT'S JUST
A PRE-ENGAGEMENT.
IT'S EXCITING.
YOU KNOW,
IT'S YOUNG LOVE.
I HAD IT ONCE.
A MAN I LOVED.
- HERE'S YOUNG MAEBY'S BLOUSE.
- AND THEN THINGS
TOOK A TURN SOMEHOW.
- MASTER BLUTH.
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
IN A WEEK'S TIME.
- OH, ACTUALLY,
YOU TRIED TO PUT A BANGER
IN MY MOUTH THIS MORNING.
- OH, WAS IT THIS MORN--
WELL, I'M SORRY.
I'M JUST SO EXHAUSTED.
- SO I'M JUST GONNA
TALK TO MY SON.
I'M GONNA TELL HIM
THAT I'M AGAINST THIS.
I DON'T--I DON'T LIKE HER.
- YOU KNOW,
MAYBE IF YOU STOP JUDGING HER,
HE'D TRUST YOU.
LOOK, IF YOU SAY NO,
YOU'RE JUST GONNA
DRIVE HIM RIGHT TO HER.
- HEY, DAD.
CAN YOU DRIVE ME TO ANN'S?
N-N-N...
Y-YES.
- GREAT. I'LL WAIT IN THE CAR.
- I DON'T THINK THAT WORKED.
narrator:
MEANWHILE, GOB WENT TO CHECK
ON THE ONE FRIEND WHO
DIDN'T MIND HAVING HIM AROUND.
- GET YOUR LOSER HAND
OUT OF MY ASS.
HELLO, SON.
- OH, DAD.
I THOUGHT--DAD?
THIS IS WHERE
YOU'VE BEEN HI--
MICHAEL.
- I JUST CAME BACK
BECAUSE OF YOUR MOTHER.
SHE'S WITH MY BROTHER
ON MY ANNIVERSARY.
BUT I GOT AN IDEA
FROM GEORGE MICHAEL.
I NEED TO RECOMMIT MYSELF
TO YOUR MOTHER.
- HER?
- BUT YOU GOTTA
GET ME INTO THAT PARTY.
THEN YOU GOTTA
TAKE ME TO THIS CHURCH.
I FOUND THIS BROCHURE
THAT ANN LEFT BEHIND.
- WELL, THAT'S GONNA BE TOUGH.
I'M NOT REALLY ALL THAT INVITED.
- I GOT IT ALL WORKED OUT,
BUT I NEED A LIMOUSINE.
- I--I CAN DO THIS, DAD.
I'M GONNA MAKE YOU PROUD.
- NEVER TOO LATE TO START.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
DROVE TO ANN'S HOUSE,
WHERE HE FINALLY
GOT TO MEET ANN'S PARENTS.
- THIS IS MY FATHER,
PASTOR TERRY VEAL.
- HELLO.
- OH, PASTOR.
I-I DIDN'T KNOW.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME.
- I TOLD YOU.
- I DIDN'T--NO, YOU DIDN'T.
- PEOPLE TREAT YOU
SO DIFFERENTLY
WHEN THEY FIND OUT
YOU'RE A MAN OF GOD.
- OH, BELIEVE ME, I KNOW.
- OH, ARE YOU A CHURCHGOING MAN?
- I AM.
SOMETIMES. YES.
I DON'T GO RELIGIOUSLY.
I MEAN,
I'M NOT A NUT ABOUT IT.
BECAUSE THERE IS
NO SUCH THING AS A NUT
WHEN IT COMES TO RELIGION,
PASTOR.
- I'VE MET A FEW.
- I'M SURE IF YOU'D LOOK
A LITTLE BIT CLOSER,
YOU'LL FIND
SOME VERY EARNEST PEOPLE
THAT ARE JUST
DOING THEIR BEST.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN', DAD?
- I'M NOT SURE.
WHY DON'T YOU TWO KIDS RUN ALONG
AND LET US GET TO KNOW EACH
OTHER A BIT BETTER?
THANK YOU.
- MAYBE I SHOULD GET MY WIFE.
HONEY.
- OKAY.
- THIS IS GEORGE MICHAEL'S
FATHER.
- THIS IS YOUR WIFE.
DIDN'T--DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU COULD REMARRY.
- WHAT?
- IS THIS ANN'S MOTHER?
- I'M MRS. VEAL.
- I'M SORRY. I JUST--
I DID NOT EXPECT
SOMEBODY SO YOUNG.
- NEXT YOU'RE GONNA SAY
HOW ANN AND I CAN BE SISTERS.
- NO, I'D NEVER SAY THAT.
LISTEN, I'M HERE BECAUSE
I THINK THAT MY SON MIGHT BE
PLANNING ON ASKING YOUR DAUGHTER
TO GET PRE-ENGAGED.
- OH, MY GOSH.
WELL, THAT IS SOMETHING
TO CELEBRATE.
CAN WE OPEN UP
SOME SPARKLING APPLE CIDER?
- MM, NO.
- OH, DID YOU WANT US TO
GO DOWN TO THE LIQUOR STORE
AND GET YOU SOME LIQUOR?
- NO.
DON'T YOU THINK
THEY'RE A BIT TOO YOUNG?
- OH, WE GOT SERIOUS
AROUND HIS AGE.
WELL, WHO CAN BLAME YOU?
YOU GOTTA LOCK THAT DOWN.
BUT I-I JUST--
I'M NOT QUITE SURE
THAT THEY'RE READY.
- MICHAEL, IN MY EXPERIENCE,
THERE IS NO RECIPE
FOR A PERFECT MATCH.
IT TAKES
THE LOVE OF TWO FAMILIES.
- WELL, YOU HAVEN'T
MET MY FAMILY.
narrator:
AND THAT'S WHEN MICHAEL
DEVISED A NEW PLAN
TO WIN THE VEALS' DISAPPROVAL.
- YOU HAVEN'T MET MY FAMILY.
YOU SHOULD MEET MY FAMILY.
WE'RE GONNA BE HAVING
AN ANNIVERSARY PARTY.
- WHAT A WONDERFUL SURPRISE.
WE WOULD LOVE TO WITNESS
A CELEBRATION OF THEIR LOVE.
- THAT WOULD BE
A WONDERFUL SURPRISE.
narrator: BUT HE DID WANT
A LITTLE BIT OF INSURANCE.
- HEY, GOB.
MOM WANTS FRANKLIN
AT THE PARTY.
YEAH. WHAT?
NO, NO, NO.
I DON'T WANT TO TALK--
HEY, FRANKLIN.
narrator:
LUCILLE WAS SETTING UP
FOR THE ANNIVERSARY PARTY
THAT SHE DIDN'T EXPECT
HER HUSBAND TO ATTEND.
- WHERE'S THE FOOD?
- SORRY.
JUST STUFFING THE MUSHROOM.
- YOU REALIZE THAT'S TOBIAS,
DON'T YOU?
- IF HE'S GONNA RAID MY CLOSET,
HE'S GONNA WORK FOR IT.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO HIS ANKLE?
narrator:
TOBIAS HAD ATTEMPTED AN ENTRANCE
THAT HE HOPED
WOULD ENCHANT HIS DAUGHTER.
- [singing in falsetto]
[glass breaking]
OHH!
WE SHAN'T BE TELLING
YOUR MOTHER THIS, SHAN'T WE?
- MAYBE YOU CAN POINT OUT
TO YOUR MOTHER
THAT YOUR FATHER
HASN'T ARRIVED YET.
- HMM.
SO...
MY FATHER'S NOT HERE.
- MAYBE HE IS.
- ANN JUST CALLED.
THEY HAD A PREDAWN MASS,
AND THEN THEY'RE
GONNA GO TO MASS, SO--
- WELL, ANN'S GOT
A GREAT DEAL OF MASS.
ANYWAY, I HOPE
THAT THE VEALS LIKE US.
WHY DON'T YOU GO
TOP OFF YOUR GANGY?
THANKS.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU INVITED THE VEALS?
- ONLY SO THAT
THEY'LL DISAPPROVE OF US.
I GOTTA KILL
THIS PRE-ENGAGEMENT SOMEHOW.
AND AFTER MOM'S SECOND VODKA,
AND AFTER BUSTER'S
SECOND JUICE BOX,
THEY'RE GONNA FORBID ANN
FROM EVEN SEEING MY SON,
MUCH LESS TAKING HIS RING,
AND I'M STILL THE GOOD GUY.
- SO THE DEVOUT
RELIGIOUS FAMILY,
THEY'RE THE BAD GUYS?
- YOU'LL UNDERSTAND WHEN
MAEBY STARTS GETTING PROPOSALS.
narrator: ACTUALLY,
MAEBY HAD GIVEN TWO THAT DAY.
- I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T READ WHAT YOU WROTE
ON THIS BUCK SLIP.
YOU'VE GOT THE HANDWRITING
OF A 15-YEAR-OLD.
- 15-YEAR-OLD.
MARRY ME!
- HEY, I'M ALMOST DONE
WITH THAT COVERAGE.
I CAN BRING IT OUT
TO YOU TONIGHT.
ARE YOU STILL
AT THE BALBOA TOWERS?
narrator: MAEBY HAD USED
HER GRANDMOTHER'S ADDRESS
SO AS NOT TO AROUSE
SUSPICION AT HOME.
THIS REQUIRED
CONVINCING THE GUARD
SHE WAS SEVERAL YEARS YOUNGER
THAN HER AGE.
- BOY, YOU GET A LOT OF MAIL
FROM THAT MOVIE STUDIO.
- I WRITE A LOT OF LETTERS
TO MOVIE STARS.
- YOU SEEM A LITTLE OLD
FOR THAT.
- BABYSIT ME.
- THAT PLACE
SEEMS SO OLD FOR YOU.
- I'LL SEND DR. EPSTEIN
YOUR COMPLIMENTS.
AND MAY I ADD, MARRY ME.
- OKAY.
narrator:
AND MAEBY REALIZED
SHE MIGHT BE IN NEED
OF A NEW DEFLECTION.
- HI, MRS. VEAL.
WELCOME.
MOM, THIS IS ANN'S MOTHER.
- ARE YOU SURE
THIS ISN'T HER SISTER?
- OH, WHAT A LOVELY
THING TO SAY.
- THAT'S AN AWFUL THING
TO SAY, MOM. PLEASE.
- I'M SO EAGER
TO MEET YOUR HUSBAND.
- YEAH. DAD ESCAPED FROM PRISON.
DID YOU NOT KNOW THAT?
narrator: IN FACT, GEORGE SR.
HAD JUST BEEN PICKED UP
BY HIS SON.
- OH, GREAT. IT'S STUCK.
ALL RIGHT.
JUST STAY DOWN
AND LET ME HANDLE THIS.
- IS THAT MR. BLUTH THERE?
- HE'S GOT US, DAD.
COME ON OUT.
- HE'S TALKING TO YOU,
YOU IDIOT.
COVER.
- I AIN'T YOUR DADDY!
HOW'S IT GOIN', BROTHER?
- YOU WANT TO POP THE TRUNK
AND ROLL THE WINDOWS DOWN,
PLEASE?
I'M JUST MESSIN' WITH YOU.
HEY, FRANKLIN.
HOW YOU DOIN', LITTLE MAN?
- SO I'M AFRAID
ANN'S WITH MY HUSBAND.
HE HAD A LAST-MINUTE
VOW RENEWAL AT THE CHAPEL.
narrator: A CALL
THAT WAS MADE BY GEORGE SR.
- SO HOW DO WE GET HER
TO THE CHURCH?
TELL HER YOU'RE IN HERE OR--
OH. NO.
COVER HER EYES
AND TAKE HER TO THE LIMO.
- NO. YOU BRING HER IN HERE,
YOU KNOCK HER OUT
WITH THIS ETHER,
AND YOU STUFF HER INTO
THIS GARMENT BAG.
ANYONE SEES, YOU DO THE SAME.
OH, HI, TOBIAS.
- OH.
[singing]
WHENEVER I GET A WEE BIT SCARED
I HUM A LITTLE TUNE
HUM DIDDLE DIDDLY
HUM DI-DO
- YOU PUT A HANDKERCHIEF
OVER HER MOUTH
FOR A COUPLE OF SECONDS.
NO MORE THAN TWO THOUGH,
'CAUSE YOU COULD KILL HER.
- I DON'T HAVE A HANDKERCHIEF.
- FINE.
PUT THE ETHER
ON THE PUPPET'S LIPS.
HAVE THE PUPPET KISS HER.
- I AIN'T KISSIN'
THAT OLD BITCH.
- THAT'S MY WIFE, YOU BASTARD!
- DAD, THAT'S MY WRIST!
[groaning]
HEY, MAN! THAT'S HIS NECK!
- HEY, GOB.
MRS. VEAL,
THIS IS MY BROTHER GOB.
WHERE'S YOUR PAL FRANKLIN?
- THROAT'S A LITTLE SORE.
AND WRIST.
[chuckles]
NICE TO MEET YOU.
- WHAT A LOVELY FAMILY.
- DOES IT SEEM THAT WAY?
WHERE'S BUSTER?
[whispers]
SHOULD HELP.
- YOU KNOW, IT'S REALLY GREAT
YOU DID THIS.
I THOUGHT
YOU DIDN'T REALLY EVEN LIKE ANN.
BUT SINCE YOU DO,
I THOUGHT MAYBE I COULD
GET YOUR OPINION.
I WAS THINKING OF GIVING HER,
LIKE, A PRE-ENGAGEMENT--
- RING?
- YEAH.
- WOW. THAT CATCHES ME
OFF GUARD, GEORGE MICHAEL.
I'M NOT SURE ABOUT THAT.
I JUST--I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S--
I THINK--I THINK
IT'S GONNA BACKFIRE ON YOU.
I THINK THAT IT COULD
BACKFIRE ON YOU,
BECAUSE IT'S GONNA SEEM
LIKE YOU'RE TAKING MARRIAGE,
UH, LIGHTLY, YOU KNOW.
AND YOU CAN'T.
IT'S VERY SACRED.
- SACRED.
- YEAH. THAT'S IT.
- ALL RIGHT.
WELL, YEAH.
YOU KNOW, IT DID KIND OF
FEEL RIGHT TO ME.
BUT, YEAH.
I'VE GOTTA TRUST YOU, RIGHT?
- THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
- DAMN. MAYBE I SHOULD--
MAYBE I SHOULD ASK
IF SHE WANTS TO GET
PRE-PRE-ENGAGED.
ADD ANOTHER--
- THE MERE FACT THAT YOU'RE
LAUGHING ABOUT MARRIAGE
MEANS THAT
YOU'RE NOT READY, OKAY?
- WHA--
narrator: AND LUCILLE
WAS ASKED TO THE KITCHEN.
- WHAT'S SO IMPORTANT
THAT YOU'RE DRAGGING ME AWAY
FROM THIS MISERABLE PARTY?
- WELL, I JUST HAD AN OLD FRIEND
WHO WANTED TO TELL YOU...
HOW MUCH I MISS YOU!
- OH, WHO LET THIS
LITTLE BLACK [bleep]--
- HEY, BROTHER.
- WHO YOU CALLIN' BROTHER,
YOU HOOK-ASS--
- MOTHER!
[horn blows]
[groaning]
- WHAT THE HELL KIND OF PUPPET
DOES BUSTER HAVE ON HIS HAND?
- JUST LET ME THINK.
GOD, FRANKLIN.
YOUR BREATH--OH, GOD.
- SO I'M REALLY GETTING EXCITED
ABOUT YOUR PROPOSAL.
- OH, YEAH.
I'M NOT GONNA DO IT NOW.
- BECAUSE ANN'S MOM
DOESN'T APPROVE OF OUR FAMILY?
OH, COME ON.
IT'S JUST SOME STUPID PLAN
YOUR FATHER WAS TRYING.
- PLAN?
WHAT PLAN?
- WELL, IT'S OFF. SORRY.
I KNOW THAT YOU WERE
EXCITED ABOUT IT.
BUT, UH, YOU KNOW,
IN THE SECULAR WORLD,
I FEEL LIKE
THEY'RE A BIT YOUNG.
- YOU KNOW, I--I DIDN'T
WANT TO SAY ANYTHING
IN FRONT OF TERRY,
BUT I AGREE.
I MEAN,
PERHAPS THERE'S SOMEONE ELSE
THEY'RE MEANT TO MEET.
- WELL, LET'S--
LET'S JUST SAY
THAT IN THE SECULAR WORLD,
ONE FINDS ONESELF
WITH THEIR FAIR SHARE
OF TEMPTATIONS.
NOT THAT ANYONE WOULD EVER ACT--
[mumbling]
MRS. VEAL.
- TAKE ME.
TAKE ME TO YOUR SECULAR WORLD.
- HEY. HEY, LISTEN.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
I CAN'T BELIEVE MY DAD.
FIRST HE'S SAYING
I NEED TO RESPECT
THE SANCTITY OF MARRIAGE,
AND THEN HE'S MAKING OUT
WITH HER ON THE BALCONY.
- I THOUGHT
HE DIDN'T EVEN LIKE ANN.
- NO, NO. MRS. VEAL.
WELL, KNOW WHAT ELSE
HE'S NOT GONNA LIKE?
I'M GETTING PRE-ENGAGED.
- GOD, THAT'S SO ROMANTIC.
- THE HELL WITH HIM.
- TAKE IT.
TAKE THE SACRED RING.
NOT THE SNAKE.
THAT DOESN'T COME OFF.
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD JUST BEEN KISSED
BY THE MOTHER
OF HIS SON'S GIRLFRIEND.
- OH, MY GOLLY!
- LISTEN.
DON'T DO THIS. DON'T DO THIS.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE'RE MAKING LOVE.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WE'RE NOT MAKING LOVE.
- I WANT
TO PLEASE YOU SECULARLY.
- WE'RE NOT GONNA DO THIS.
- BUT YOU KEPT TELLING ME
HOW BEAUTIFUL I WAS.
- I WAS SURPRISED
BECAUSE OF ANN.
WELL--
- WHY BECAUSE OF ANN?
- BECAUSE OF
AN OLD WIVES' TALE.
- OH, I'M SO ASHAMED.
- ALL RIGHT. NO--
MRS. VEAL.
- JOLLY NEWS, GOVERNOR.
YOUNG MASTER'S PROPOSING.
- GEORGE MICHAEL?
I TOLD HIM NOT TO.
HE SAID HE WOULDN'T.
- WELL, THIS WAS BEFORE
HE SAW YOU POUNDING
THAT SWEET PIECE OF VEAL.
- HE SAW THAT?
WHERE IS HE?
- OH, HE LEFT
WITH LADY LINDSAY--
- TOBIAS, WHERE ARE THEY?
- IT IS ME.
IT'S TOBIAS.
- [yelling]
WHAT HAPPENED?
- WHAT'S GOING ON?
- GOB MADE ME KISS FRANKLIN.
AND I THINK MY FATHER WAS HERE.
- MAYBE HE STILL IS.
- OH, SHUT UP.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN HE WAS HERE?
- I THINK HE WAS DRAGGING
MY MOTHER OUT WITH GOB.
- OH, YOU SHUT UP.
- WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
- WE'RE TRYIN'
TO FIGURE THAT OUT.
APPARENTLY POP-POP
KIDNAPPED GANGY,
AND I HAVE NO IDEA WHERE
GEORGE MICHAEL IS--OR LINDSAY.
- I JUST SAW THEM DRIVE OFF.
THEY'RE GONNA
GO LOOK FOR BLAND.
WHO'S THE HOTTIE?
- THIS IS ANN'S MOTHER.
- HER?
DOES SHE LOOK OLD ENOUGH
TO PLAY TOPHER GRACE'S MOM?
- WHERE DID YOU SAY ANN WAS?
- AT THE CHAPEL.
- YEAH, WE GOTTA GET DOWN THERE.
MY SON'S GONNA PRE-PROPOSE
TO YOUR DAUGHTER.
narrator: FORTUNATELY,
TOBIAS HAD RENTED A CAR
TO MAINTAIN HIS RUSE.
- I HAD THIS SHIPPED OVER
FROM "BLACKSTOOL."
IT'S WHAT I USED TO DRIVE
THE ROGER MOORES ABOUT IN.
narrator: AND LUCILLE AWOKE,
HALF IN THE BAG.
- WHAT AM I DOING
IN A NORDSTROM BAG?
- IT'S ME.
I'M TAKING YOU
TO RENEW OUR VOWS.
BUT FIRST--
- UH, DAD--
- WE MAKE LOVE.
- THE PARTITION DOESN'T
GO ALL THE WAY UP, REMEMBER?
- NO. NO.
AFTER YOUR VOWS,
I WANT TO KNOW
YOU WON'T RUN OUT ON ME AGAIN.
I NEED TO KNOW
YOU'RE IN IT FOR KEEPS.
- JUST LET ME SEE 'EM.
- SERIOUSLY, DAD.
THE RADIO DOESN'T WORK EITHER.
- GEORGE!
narrator: GOB RACED
HIS PARENTS TO THE CHURCH,
PASSING GEORGE MICHAEL
AND LINDSAY,
WHO WERE SOON FOLLOWED
BY MRS. FEATHERBOTTOM.
[horn honks]
- OH, MERCY ME!
I KEEP FORGETTING
I'M IN THE COLONIES.
narrator:
BUSTER WAS TALKING TO THE POLICE
WHEN OSCAR FOUND A CLUE.
- THEY MUST BE GOING
TO THIS CHURCH.
HE'S GOING
TO RENEW HIS VOWS.
HE'S MY TWIN BROTHER.
I KNOW HOW HE THINKS.
- THEY'RE AT
THE CHURCH OF THE GOOD SHEPHERD.
narrator:
AND AT THE CHAPEL,
PASTOR VEAL WAS OFFICIATING.
- "TO LOVE AND HONOR
YOUR SPIRIT AND FLESH.
"FIRST THE FLESH.
I WILL CARESS AND TWEAK.
"I WILL NIBBLE AND BITE.
I WILL BLOW ALTERNATINGLY
HOT AND COOL."
- OH, MAN.
I CAN'T WAIT TO GET MARRIED.
narrator:
ANN WENT TO COOL DOWN,
WHERE GEORGE MICHAEL FOUND HER.
- ANN,
I HAVE SOMETHING TO ASK YOU.
WELL, I-I REALLY LIKE YOU.
I GUESS WHAT I--
I WANT TO ASK YOU IS,
WILL YOU ONE DAY,
UH, INTEND TO MARRY ME?
AND IT WOULD BE GREAT
TO HEAR BACK ON THIS
BEFORE THE REAL HARD
A.P. STUFF KICKS IN, YOU KNOW.
- LET'S DO IT. NOW.
LET'S ACTUALLY GET MARRIED.
- RIGHT NOW?
- MY FATHER'S RIGHT IN THERE.
HE CAN DO IT
AS SOON AS HE FINISHES.
- "I'LL ALWAYS BE HERE FOR YOU
TO REST YOUR ANKLES
UPON MY SHOULDERS."
narrator: AND MICHAEL
SHOWED UP AT THE CHAPEL.
- UH, LISTEN, BUDDY.
DAD?
- UH, FASTER, PASTOR.
- STOP THIS!
STOP THIS NOW!
narrator:
OSCAR CHARGED AT GEORGE SR.,
FINALLY WILLING
TO FIGHT FOR LUCILLE.
BUT THEY DID THINK ALIKE,
AND NEITHER COULD
LAND A BLOW.
- DAD, DO US.
WE'RE READY TO GET MARRIED.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, DON'T DO THIS
JUST TO GET BACK AT ME, OKAY?
WHAT YOU SAW ON THE BALCONY--
UH, MRS. VEAL
STARTED KISSING ME.
narrator: THIS PART OF IT
WAS NEWS TO GEORGE MICHAEL.
UNFORTUNATELY,
IT WAS ALSO NEWS TO PASTOR VEAL.
- YOU KISSED MY WIFE?
- NO. SHE STARTED KISSING ME.
YOU REALLY SHOULD
LOCK THAT DOWN.
narrator:
AND PASTOR VEAL, TOO,
WAS READY
TO FIGHT FOR THE WOMAN HE LOVED.
[yells]
- AH. FINALLY.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
narrator:
THE POLICE HAD BEEN DELAYED
WHEN THEY THOUGHT THEY'D
CORNERED A KIDNAPPING SUSPECT.
- PUT YOUR HANDS UP,
OR WE'LL TAKE THAT AS A SIGN
OF AGGRESSION AGAINST US.
- THEY'RE NOT UP!
- HE'S AGGRESSIVE!
- YEAH,
GOT A LITTLE HOT OUT THERE.
- OH, WELL, IT'S GETTING
PRETTY HOT IN HERE.
- SHE'S MINE!
- NO. SHE'S MINE.
- OSCAR, I DON'T WANT HER.
I DON'T WANT EITHER OF THEM.
- OH. SORRY.
WHERE'S MY BROTHER?
- LOOK AT ALL THE BOBBIES.
[chuckles]
OH, NO. MY WIG
SEEMS TO HAVE RUN OFF.
narrator:
ON GEORGE SR., AS IT TURNED OUT.
- WHO IS THIS GUY?
- THIS GUY IS MY HUSBAND.
- TERRY,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
I FELL UNDER THE SPELL
OF THAT HORRIBLE SECULAR FAMILY.
FORGIVE ME.
- COULD'VE USED THAT
HORRIBLE FAMILY STUFF
ABOUT A HALF HOUR AGO.
- I HOPE YOU NOTICE
I DIDN'T RUN.
- YOU FOUGHT FOR ME.
- WHAT I MEANT TO SAY IS I--
I THINK I BROKE MY ANKLE.
- LET'S ALTERNATE
HOT AND COOL ON THAT.
- GUESS THE WEDDING'S OFF?
- YEAH. THAT'S OKAY, DAD.
YOU KNOW, WE WERE--
WE WERE TALKING, AND WE THINK
THAT WE WERE DOIN' IT
FOR THE WRONG REASONS.
- YEAH? WELL, YOU KNOW,
YOU HAVE SO MUCH TO EXPERIENCE
BEFORE YOU MAKE A COMMITMENT
THAT YOU'RE NOT READY FOR.
YOU KNOW?
YOU JUST NEED TO GET
TO KNOW EACH OTHER BETTER,
AND THEN YOU CAN BE COMFORTABLE
GOING ALL THE WAY WITH IT.
- DO YOU MEAN IT?
- YES. THIS TIME
I'M BEING HONEST WITH YOU.
- THANKS, DAD.
- OKAY.
- IT SOUNDS LIKE YOUR FATHER
JUST GAVE US PERMISSION
TO START DOING IT.
YOU MUST TEACH ME,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
YOU MUST TEACH ME
THE WAYS OF THE SECULAR FLESH.
[man singing]
HEY, WHAT YOU TRYIN'
TO SAY TO ME
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
- THAT DOESN'T BOTHER YOU.
narrator:
BUSTER FINDS SOMEONE ELSE
INTERESTED IN KISSING HIS HOOK.
- OH, GOD!
- DRUG DOG'S GOT SOMETHING.
GET HIM, BENNETT!
narrator: SO BUSTER GETS
A HOOK REPLACEMENT.
- THEY'RE NOT GONNA LET YOU IN
AT THE COUNTRY CLUB WITH THAT.
- I DON'T WANT NO PART OF YOUR
TIGHT-ASS COUNTRY CLUB,
YOU FREAK BITCH!