- NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING,
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH HAD SET UP
A MEETING WITH CAL CULLEN,
OWNER OF ONE OF THE LARGEST
PARCELS OF LAND
IN ORANGE COUNTY.
- I HOPE THAT I CAN PROVE TO YOU
THAT WE HAVE
A VERY IMPRESSIVE COMPANY.
- WELL, YOUR FAMILY
DID NOT COME OFF WELL
ON LAST NIGHT'S "SCANDALMAKERS."
- "SCANDALMAKERS" WAS A SHOW
THAT REENACTED
HEADLINE-GRABBING STORIES.
THE LATEST WAS
ABOUT THE BLUTH FAMILY,
THE RIGHTS OF WHICH HAD BEEN
SIGNED AWAY BY TOBIAS
IN EXCHANGE FOR THE PART
OF GEORGE SR.
- WHEN ALLEGATIONS SURFACED HE'D
ILLEGALLY BUILT HOMES IN IRAQ,
GEORGE BLUTH SR., ASSISTED
BY HIS SECRETARY, KITTY,
ESCAPED THE COUNTRY.
- DUE TO POOR ACTING,
THE BURDEN OF THE STORY
WAS PLACED ON THE NARRATOR.
- ONLY TO BE FOUND HIDING UNDER
ONE OF THE HOMES THAT HE BUILT.
- HE WAS ACTUALLY FOUND
IN A HOLE NEAR THE HOUSE,
BUT THIS INATTENTION
TO DETAIL WAS TYPICAL
OF THE LAZINESS THE
SHOW'S NARRATOR WAS KNOWN FOR.
- I CAN'T SURVIVE
UNDER THE HOUSE.
PERHAPS AN ATTIC
SHALL I SEEK.
- REAL SHODDY NARRATING.
JUST PURE CRAP.
- BUT WE'RE BACK ON TRACK,
AND WE ARE SCANDAL-FREE.
- HEY! YOU START
THE MEETING WITHOUT ME?
- MOTHER, UH,
THIS IS CAL CULLEN.
YOU REMEMBER MY MOTHER, LUCILLE.
WE'RE RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF TALKING
ABOUT THIS EXCITING GIVEAWAY
SPA PACKAGE TO ENTICE BUYERS.
- YOU KNOW, HE'S NEVER TAKEN
ME ANYWHERE.
OH, NO.
WE HAVE TO LIVE
HIGH AND DRY.
- WELL, YOU'RE
CERTAINLY NOT DRY.
MICHAEL, I'M NOT A PRUDE,
BUT IT'S 1:00 IN THE AFTERNOON.
IS YOUR MOTHER DRUNK?
- I'D HAVE TO GET UP PRETTY EARY
TO GET DRUNK BY 1:00.
[laughs]
- AS IT TURNS OUT,
SHE HAD GOTTEN UP EARLY
AND HAD TAKEN PAIN MEDICATION
BECAUSE OF A HANGOVER-RELATED
HEADACHE.
HOWEVER, SHE MISTOOK THE
"DROWSY EYE" ALCOHOL WARNING
FOR A "WINKING EYE"
ALCOHOL SUGGESTION.
FORTUNATELY, SHE HAD
THE GOOD SENSE
NOT TO DRIVE HERSELF
TO THE MEETING.
- NO.
I'LL CALL FOR A CAR.
- UNFORTUNATELY, THIS WAS AFTER
A FAILED ATTEMPT TO DO SO.
- WHO THE HELL PUT--
- MICHAEL, I'M SORRY.
I CANNOT DO BUSINESS WITH YOU.
I MEAN, I COULDN'T AFFORD
TO END UP ON "SCANDALMAKERS."
- OH, YOU COULD AFFORD
TO DO ANYTHING YOU WANT.
YOU'RE JUST A BIG CHICKEN.
A-COODLE-DOODLE-DOO.
A-COO--
thump!
- MICHAEL REALIZED THAT
IT MIGHT BE TIME
TO DEAL WITH HIS MOTHER'S
APPARENT PROBLEM.
- OKAY, THAT SEEMS AS GOOD A
PLACE AS ANY TO END THE MEETING.
- NO, I'M NOT DOING ANOTHER
INTERVENTION WITH HER.
LAST TIME, I FELT
TERRIBLE FOR A WEEK.
- ONE YEAR EARLIER, THE FAMILY
HAD TRIED AN INTERVENTION.
- YOU'RE POURING A DRINK?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WHAT IF SHE'S MAD?
- GOOD POINT.
- PERHAPS I'LL HAVE
A LITTLE SIP OF SOMETHING.
- GUYS, WHAT COULD SHE
DO TO US?
DO WE HAVE ANYTHING
SINGLE MALT?
- AND ALTHOUGH THE INTERVENTION
DIDN'T WORK--
- WE THINK YOU HAVE A PROLLEN.
- YOU'RE A MESH.
- IT TURNED INTO ONE OF THE
BLUTH FAMILY'S BETTER PARTIES.
[whimpering and piano plunking]
[laughter]
- WELL, MAYBE AN INTERVENTION
IS THE WRONG APPROACH.
WHAT ABOUT REHAB?
SHE WAS JUST A MESS
AT THE MEETING.
WHERE WERE YOU, BY THE WAY?
I COULD'VE USED
YOUR HELP WITH MOM.
- I BELIEVE I TOLD YOU I WAS
GONNA BE OUT FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
IT'S SPRING BREAK.
NOT THAT I CAN ENJOY IT.
MY REPUTATION'S BEEN RUINED BY
THAT JERK PHILLIP LITT,
WHO PUT MY ONE MAGIC-SHOW FLUB
ON HIS DVD.
- GOB HAD PERFORMED A MAGIC ACT
AT AN EARLIER SPRING BREAK
TO GET EXPOSURE ON THE
BEST-SELLING VIDEO SERIES,
"GIRLS WITH LOW SELF-ESTEEM."
- OR TWO FLUBS OR WHATEVER.
- THERE WERE SEVEN FLUBS,
AND AFTER THE SHOW,
HE SIGNED A RELEASE.
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA USE THE TIME
THAT I SCREWED UP, RIGHT?
- THAT WASN'T PART OF THE ACT?
COME ON, MAN, I'D NEVER DO
ANYTHING TO EMBARRASS YOU.
[squawking]
PLEASE.
crunch!
- OH. UH, YOU DON'T KNOW
A GOOD BIRD HOSPITAL, DO YOU?
- YOU'RE GETTING
ALL THIS, RIGHT?
- WELL, AT LEAST
THE ORANGE COUNTY REGISTER
DIDN'T SAY OF YOUR PERFORMANCE,
"IF THIS IS WHO GEORGE SR. IS,
LET'S HOPE HE REMAINS MISSING."
MEANWHILE, THEY LOVED
DAVE ATTELL'S RISKY CHOICE
OF WEARING CUTOFFS
WHILE PORTRAYING ME.
- IN FACT, MR. ATTELL
WAS PORTRAYING
TOBIAS'S ACTUAL
NEVER-NUDE AFFLICTION,
BUT THIS PERPLEXED
THE "SCANDALMAKERS" AUDIENCE,
DUE TO THE UNFOCUSED NATURE
OF THE NARRATOR'S EXPLANATION.
- NO, I THINK MINE'S WORSE.
YOU SHOULD'VE SEEN WHAT HAPPENED
TO ME ON THE BOARDWALK TODAY.
THEY WERE LAUGHING AT ME.
ME!
[chuckling]
- THOSE TAPES ARE AWFUL:
WOMEN TRICKED INTO
TAKING THEIR TOPS OFF.
I HAVE A DAUGHTER I DON'T
WANT CORRUPTED BY THE MEDIA.
- UNBEKNOWNST TO LINDSAY,
MAEBY WAS A FAIRLY PROMINENT
MEMBER OF THE MEDIA,
AS SHE HAD
SECRETLY CONNED HER WAY
INTO A JOB
AS A FILM EXECUTIVE.
- THIS YOUNG MAN ON THE BEACH
SCRIPT SUCKS.
SHE'D GO TO THE GUY JUST
'CAUSE HE SAID SHE'S AWESOME?
YOU CALL THAT DIALOGUE?
- HEY, I DIDN'T WRITE IT.
- NO, BUT YOU'RE GONNA FIX IT.
IT'S A SPRING BREAK MOVIE.
GET DOWN THERE AND FIND OUT
WHAT THEY SOUND LIKE.
- OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
I LOOK COLLEGE-AGED?
- I'M NOT DRUNK.
BUT I'M WILLING TO BE.
HINT.
- OH, MORT, YOU'RE GONNA BE
SO EASY TO BLACKMAIL. HINT.
- THIS PIG, PHILLIP LITT,
IS OUT THERE ASKING GIRLS
TO TAKE THEIR TOPS OFF.
IT'S AN OUTRAGE.
- WELL, OF COURSE
YOU FEEL THAT WAY.
YOU'RE JEALOUS.
YOU'RE A SURFBOARD.
BUT I DO AGREE HE IS A PIG.
HEY! WHAT THE HELL
WAS THAT FOR?
- CAN WE STOP WORRYING ABOUT
GIRLS WITH LOW SELF-ESTEEM
AND START FOCUSING ON SOBERING
UP THE WOMAN WHO GAVE US OURS?
SERIOUSLY,
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT REHAB?
- SHE WON'T GO WILLINGLY.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
- MAY I MAKE A SUGGESTION?
GET IMPLANTS. REALLY.
WHA--COME ON!
THIS STUFF IS EXPENSIVE!
- AND SO MICHAEL SET OUT
TO CONVINCE HIS MOTHER
THAT SHE NEEDED HELP.
- HELLO? HELLO?
I HAVE A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
- DID I WIN THE PRIZE?
- YOU WON THE PRIZE.
- I WON THE PRIZE!
I WON THE PRIZE--FOR WHAT?
- WE WERE GONNA GIVE
ONE EMPLOYEE A WEEK AT THE SPA.
WE WERE EVEN GONNA
PUT THEM IN THE AD,
BUT THEN I THOUGHT,
"WHAT ABOUT MOM?
SHE'S ELEGANT.
SHE DESERVES IT."
I WAS GONNA TELL YOU AT
THE OFFICE, BUT THEN I THOUGHT,
"NO. IF I BRING HER AROUND NOW,
SHE MIGHT VOMIT
ON THE OVERHEAD PROJECTOR."
LET'S JUST WAIT TILL SHE'S
CRAWLING AROUND ON HER OWN.
- I'M SO EMBARRASSED ABOUT THAT.
I DON'T THINK I WAS SUPPOSED
TO DRINK WITH MY MEDICATION.
- ACTUALLY, IT WASN'T EVEN
HER MEDICATION.
- OF COURSE, I CAN'T TAKE OSCAR
TO AN ELEGANT PLACE.
HIS ONLY REMAINING PAIR OF PANTS
BLEW APART THE OTHER DAY.
I WAS THINKING THAT I WOULD
GO WITH YOU FOR THE WEEK.
- SO WHAT?
I JUST STAY HERE ALONE?
I'M NOT EXACTLY EQUIPPED
TO RUN THIS PLACE BY MYSELF!
YOU CAN'T JUST
LEAVE ME HERE ALONE!
HAVE A GREAT TRIP.
- BUT IT WOULDN'T TURN OUT
TO BE A GREAT TRIP AT ALL.
HELLO. WELCOME
TO SHADY PINES REHAB.
JUST SIGN RIGHT HERE.
- REHAB? THIS ISN'T A SPA.
THIS ISN'T A SPA!
- COME HERE. WAIT. GET HER.
COME HERE, MOM!
- WE GOT A RUNNER!
- AS MICHAEL'S MOTHER WAS BEING
HELD AGAINST HER WILL,
GEORGE SR. WAS ABOUT
TO BE CONFRONTED
WITH A SIMILAR PROBLEM.
- KITTY.
HOW'D YOU FIND ME?
- I THOUGHT YOU WERE DEAD
UNTIL I SAW "SCANDALMAKERS!"
- THEY GOT SO MUCH WRONG.
BUT SOMETHING ABOUT YOUR
SON-IN-LAW'S COMMENT,
"PERHAPS AN ATTIC SHALL I SEEK"
HAD THE RING OF TRUTH TO IT.
- NOTICE IT WASN'T SOMETHING
THE NARRATOR SAID.
- YOU ABANDONED ME IN MEXICO!
- KITTY, HONEY,
I--I KNOW YOU'RE MAD.
- STOP TALKING, GEORGE.
YOU STOP TALKING!
I AM IN CHARGE NOW.
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
- NO, I CAN'T. I CA--
I HAVE A LIFE HERE.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO--
WHO DEPEND ON ME.
- FINE. BUT I CAN'T MAKE
ANY PROMISES
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS TO THAT
COOLER OF EVIDENCE I HAVE.
- IF I COULD JUST HAVE
A MOMENT TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
- MEANWHILE,
AT THE BANANA STAND,
MAEBY WAS HOPING TO FIND
SOME WITTY BANTER
WITH WHICH TO AUTHENTICATE
HER FEATURE FILM.
- I WANT THE HOT CHICK
TO SERVE ME.
- WHAT OTHER WORDS WOULD YOU
USE TO DESCRIBE ME?
- UM, SHE'S 15,
AND SHE'S MY COUSIN.
- SO?
- SO YOU CAN'T TOUCH
YOUR COUSIN--MY COUSIN.
YOU KNOW, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO STICK AROUND.
I COULD JUST WORK LATE TONIGHT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER, 'CAUSE,
YOU KNOW, MY GIRLFRIEND,
ANN, SHE'S OUT OF TOWN.
WHICH ACTUALLY KIND OF
LUCKY IN THE END,
'CAUSE ALL THESE GUYS
WOULD BE COMING ON TO HER.
- YEAH, YOU REALLY DODGED
A BULLET THERE.
- NEARBY, PHILLIP LITT
WAS MAKING HIS LATEST VIDEO.
- EVERYBODY GATHER AROUND!
GATHER AROUND!
LADIES, HERE'S THE DEAL.
WE HAVE HATS.
YOU HAVE BREASTS.
YOU SHOW YOUR BREASTS,
YOU GET A HAT, OKAY?
SO IF ANYONE WANTS
TO GET BACK AT DADDY,
NOW'S THE TIME.
WHOO! WAIT. CUT, CUT.
WE GOT A SURFBOARD IN THE SHOT.
- SURFBOARD. STOP TAPE.
- WE'RE HERE TO STOP YOU FROM
TAKING ADVANTAGE OF THESE GIRLS.
[booing]
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE SASSY. YOU'RE SEXY.
YOU SPEAK YOUR MIND.
THERE'S NOTHIN' HOTTER.
- GIVE HER A HAT, BARRY.
- I DON'T WANT A HAT.
I WANT YOU TO LEAVE
THESE WOMEN ALONE.
- I'M GIVING THEM A CHANCE
TO BE IDOLIZED,
WHICH IS AN OPPORTUNITY
THESE WOMEN ARE NEVER
GONNA HAVE AGAIN.
- I WANT TO BE IDOLIZED.
- YEAH, YOU DO!
[cheering]
- EILEEN, STOP IT.
YOU'VE GOT NOTHING
TO GAIN FROM THAT.
- THAT'S EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
YOU ALREADY HAVE A HAT.
- COME ON, GIRLS!
- THIS IS NO WAY TO GET
YOUR DADDIES TO NOTICE YOU!
- NEARBY, LINDSAY'S OWN DADDY
FAILED TO NOTICE HER
AS HE WAS BEING TAKEN
TO A LOCAL MOTEL
WHERE HE REFUSED
KITTY'S SEXUAL ADVANCES.
- YOU PROMISED ME POWER
AND A CHILD,
AND I HAVE NEITHER.
I'M GONNA TAKE CARE
OF THIS PROBLEM ON MY OWN.
- YOU NEVER PROMISE
CRAZY A BABY.
- GEORGE SR. WAS ABANDONED
AND LONGED FOR LUCILLE,
AND BUSTER FELT THE SAME WAY.
- UPON HER KNEE,
SO FINE TO BE...
- WHO-HOO-HOO!
- MOTHER AND BOY...
- RESTLESS, BUSTER WENT
TO THE KITCHEN
TO FIND SOMETHING
TO HELP HIM SLEEP
WHEN HE CAME ACROSS LUCILLE'S
EMERGENCY STASH OF WINE...
- MOTHERLODE
- WHICH HE MISTOOK
FOR A GIANT JUICE BOX.
- MAMA'S MOVIN' ON...
- MAMA'S ALL ALONE...
- IT WAS THE FIRST TASTE
OF ALCOHOL BUSTER HAD
SINCE HE WAS NURSING.
- MAMA'S GOT THE STUFF--
- MAMA!
- AND MICHAEL, HIS MOTHER
NO LONGER A THREAT...
- THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR YOUR UNDERSTANDING, SIR.
- MET AGAIN WITH CAL CULLEN.
- AS I MENTIONED ON THE PHONE,
SHE DID SEEK HELP.
AND IT WAS EXTREMELY MOVING
WHEN SHE FINALLY ADMITTED
THAT SHE HAS A PROBLEM.
- WE'LL TAKE GOOD CARE OF YOU
HERE AT SHADY PINES.
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU,
YOU SON OF A--
- SHADY PINES IS A WONDERFUL
FACILITY UP THERE ON THE HILL.
YOU KNOW, THEY USED TO FILM
"SUGARFOOT" UP THERE.
- NO!
- WERE YOU A FAN
OF "SUGARFOOT?"
- I LOVED IT.
- "SUGARFOOT" HAD BEEN
OFF THE AIR
12 YEARS BEFORE
MICHAEL WAS BORN.
- WELL, SING THE THEME SONG
OF SUGARFOOT ALONG WITH ME.
- SUGARFOOT, YEAH,
SUGARFOOT...
- SUGARFOOT, YES...
- EASY LOPIN', CATTLE-ROPIN'
SUGARFOOT...
- NA, NA, NA...
- CAREFREE AS THE TUMBLEWEEDS--
- HUCHAH!
- OH, WHAT THE HELL.
YOU'RE A GOOD KID.
LET'S MAKE THE DEAL.
- OH, GREAT.
I'VE GOT PAPERS--
- MICHAEL!
REMEMBER ME?
PERHAPS THIS'LL JOG YOUR MEMORY.
- OH, THEY'RE CROOKED.
- I'VE KIDNAPPED YOUR FATHER,
MICHAEL,
AND I HAVE A COOLER
FULL OF EVIDENCE
THAT WILL BRING DOWN
THIS CORRUPT COMPANY
UNLESS YOUR MOTHER
MEETS ME TODAY
AT 4:00 AT SENOR TADPOLE'S.
SPRING BREAK.
WHOO!
- DAD?
- MICHAEL'S FATHER
HAD JUST BEEN KIDNAPPED...
- [cell phone rings]
- HELLO?
- AND THEN HE RECEIVED A CALL
THAT HIS BROTHER
HAD BEEN FOUND DRUNK.
- NO, I'M FINE.
I'M TELLING YOU.
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
I REALIZE THAT MAYBE
I AM BETTER OFF WITHOUT HER.
- YEAH, WELL, WE'VE GOTTA
BRING HER BACK.
- OH, THANK GOD!
- SO IF WE WANT TO GET
THAT EVIDENCE BACK, AND DAD,
KITTY IS INSISTING
ON A MEETING WITH MOM.
- WHAT CAN MOM DO FOR HER?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I'VE GOTTA GET
MY HANDS ON THAT EVIDENCE.
PROBLEM IS I JUST
CHECKED HER INTO REHAB.
THEY'RE NOT EXACTLY GONNA
LET ME CHECK HER OUT
AND TAKE HER TO A BAR.
SO, GOB, I NEED YOU TO HELP ME
SNEAK HER PAST THE GUARDS.
- WELL, GEE, I DIDN'T THINK
THE WOMAN I'D BE CHECKING OUT
AT SPRING BREAK WOULD BE MOM.
- SHE'S BETTER LOOKING
THAN THE WHORES YOU DATE.
- DON'T CALL MY ESCORTS WHORES.
- MOM'S STILL GOT IT!
- I DON'T DATE WHORES!
- STOP IT!
STOP IT!
THIS OBJECTIFICATION OF WOMEN
HAS TO STOP!
- IT'S JUST MOM AND WHORES.
- NO, HOW WOULD YOU LIKE IT?
ACTUALLY,
THAT'S NOT A BAD IDEA.
I SHOULD TURN THE TABLES ON MEN
AND SEE HOW THEY LIKE
BEING OBJECTIFIED.
- MEN WITH LOW SELF-ESTEEM.
GET THEIR CLOTHES OFF.
- THAT IS A GREAT--
[grunts]
THAT IS A GREAT
SOCIAL STATEMENT.
I SHALL GET THE VIDEO CAMERA.
THIS IS RIPE FOR PARODY.
THIS IS RIPE!
- HE JUST WANTS TO SEE
BOYS' LINUSES.
- OH, GOD.
HERE WE GO.
- AND SO MICHAEL WENT BACK
TO SEE HIS MOM.
- I--I KNOW THAT YOU'RE
UPSET WITH ME
BECAUSE I BROUGHT YOU HERE
UNDER FALSE PRETENSES,
BUT I REALLY WAS WORRIED
ABOUT YOU.
- OH, PLEASE.
I'VE BEEN DRINKING
SINCE BEFORE YOU WERE BORN.
SO IF ALCOHOL
IS THE REASON I'M HERE,
I'VE GOT NEWS FOR YOU, BUB.
IT'S THE ONLY REASON
YOU'RE HERE TOO.
- HEY, YOU'RE MEAN SOBER TOO.
UH, LISTEN.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
KITTY HAS SHOWN UP,
AND SHE GOT AHOLD OF DAD.
- SHE FOUND HIM IN THE ATTIC?
THEY HAD A RERUN
OF "SCANDALMAKERS" LAST NIGHT.
EVERYBODY FIGURED IT OUT.
- SHE WOULD LIKE
TO MEET YOU AT A BAR.
SHE SAYS SHE'S GOT SOME EVIDENCE
THAT COULD BRING THE BUSINESS
DOWN IF YOU DON'T GO.
- YOU'RE SENDING ME
INTO A BAR?
ARE YOU SURE YOU CAN TRUST ME
TO MAKE DECISIONS FOR MYSELF?
- I JUST NEED YOU TO FIND
OUT WHAT SHE WANTS, OKAY,
WHILE I CHECK
ALL THE LOCAL MOTELS FOR DAD.
- ALL RIGHT.
BUT HERE'S WHAT I WANT.
A SPA WEEKEND WITH YOU.
A REAL ONE.
I WANT TO SPEND
SPRING BREAK WITH YOU.
- YOU HAVE HIGH SELF-ESTEEM,
RIGHT?
- NOT AFTER BEING IN HERE.
IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
- MICHAEL, MOM!
WE'VE GOTTA GO NOW.
I CREATED A DIVERSION.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
I'D LIKE TO CHECK MY UNCLE
IN FOR REHAB.
- I THOUGHT WE WERE BUYING ME
SOME PANTS.
- OH, OF COURSE YOU THINK THAT.
YOU'RE HIGH AS A KITE!
HE NEEDS HELP!
ANY-- HE NEEDS HELP!
- AND SO LUCILLE WAS ABLE TO MET
WITH KITTY AT SENOR TADPOLE'S.
- I WANT WHAT'S DUE TO ME--
A BLUTH SON.
AND I KNOW
YOU HAVE THE MATERIAL.
- KITTY WAS RIGHT.
TEN YEARS EARLIER,
GEORGE SR. WAS TAKING AN
EXPERIMENTAL HAIR GROWTH DRUG.
FEARING DAMAGE
TO HIS FERTILITY,
HE FROZE A SPECIMEN
OF HIS REPRODUCTIVE MATERIAL
IN CASE HE EVER WANTED
ANOTHER CHILD.
SOON, NEWS CAME OUT
THAT THE DRUG,
ALTHOUGH SOMEWHAT SUCCESSFUL,
WREAKED HAVOC
ON THE CENTRAL NERVOUS SYSTEM.
- SO WHAT DO YOU NEED ME FOR?
HE'S NOT TAKING
THE MONKEY DRUG ANYMORE.
AND YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S GOT HIM, NOT ME.
- OH, YOU KNOW WHY.
- HE WON'T TOUCH ME.
HE SAID HE DOESN'T CHEAT
ON HIS WIFE ANYMORE.
- HE SAID THAT?
- DRINKING CONTEST!
- TELL YOU WHAT.
I'LL DRINK YOU FOR IT.
- OH, I HEARD YOU DON'T HANDLE
YOUR BOOZE SO WELL ANYMORE.
- SO THIS SHOULD BE
EASY FOR YOU.
THAT ONE DIDN'T COUNT.
- AND MICHAEL MET UP WITH GOB
TO TRY AND FIND THEIR FATHER.
- I GOT IT.
FROM THE BANANA STAND FREEZER.
THE EXACT SAME KIND OF COOLER
THAT'S IN THE PHOTO WITH DAD.
- WHAT DO WE NEED
ANOTHER COOLER FOR?
- AH, POOR MICHAEL.
YOU DO NOT THINK
LIKE A MAGICIAN.
SUCH A "HOW'D HE DO DAT?"
- UH-HUH.
- IT'S A CLASSIC
BAIT AND SWITCH.
- THIS IS A DECOY COOLER.
WE TAKE IT IN, SWITCH IT
WITH THE ONE FROM THE PHOTO
AND GET OUT OF THERE.
KITTY COMES BACK.
EVERYTHING'S NORMAL.
IT'S LIKE WE WERE NEVER THERE.
- BUT DAD'S GONE.
- LONG GONE.
BUT IT BUYS US ALL THE TIME
IN THE WORLD.
I GOT IT BACK, MIKEY.
THE SELF-CONFIDENCE.
I AM A MAGICIAN!
- I'M SAYING, WHEN KITTY COMES
BACK, NOTICES DAD'S GONE,
FIRST THING SHE'S GONNA DO
IS CHECK THE COOLER,
SEE IF THE EVIDENCE
IS STILL THERE.
BUYS US, LIKE, ONE SECOND.
- I AM A WORTHLESS MAGICIAN.
- NOT TRUE.
- NO, I CAN'T EVEN DO
ONE SIMPLE TRICK.
I'M COVERED IN SWEAT!
LOOK AT ME!
- DON'T SAY THAT.
IT'S A GREAT TRICK.
WOULD'VE BEEN FLAWLESS
IF YOU HAD A DECOY DAD TOO.
- DAMN IT.
AND I USED A GUY
THAT LOOKED JUST LIKE HIM
IN MY LAST BAIT AND SWITCH.
- OW! OW! OW! OW!
- WELL, I'M NO LONGER
NEEDED HERE.
- NO, NO, NO.
I THINK THE COOLER'S
ACTUALLY GONNA HELP US.
THE EXTRA SECOND THAT IT BUYS US
COULD BE THE DIFFERENCE.
- GREAT, JUST GIVE ME A COUPLE
OF MINUTES TO CATCH MY BREATH.
[sighs]
- LUCILLE, MINUTES OUT OF REHAB,
WAS ENGAGING
IN A DRINKING CONTEST
AT THE BEHEST OF HER SON.
[crowd cheering]
- LET ME KNOW WHEN YOU'RE READY,
DEAR.
- KEEP MIXING!
- WHILE RIGHT OUTSIDE THE BAR...
- I KNOW WHAT THE SHAPE
OF A BANANA REMINDS YOU OF,
AND I KNOW THAT WHEN I SAY
"NUTS," IT MAKES YOU GIGGLE.
- [giggling]
- BUT DO YOU HAVE
ANY OTHER RESPONSE
TO "HERE'S A BANANA
WITH NUTS"?
- [hysterical laughter]
- WHY ARE WE EVEN GOING AFTER
THIS IDIOT DEMOGRAPHIC?
- MAEBY, DON'T YOU GET IT?
THEY'RE NOT EVEN EATING THESE.
THEY JUST LIKE SAYING
BANANAS AND NUTS.
AND I WON'T--
I WON'T TELL YOU WHY.
THAT'S YOUR FATHER'S JOB.
- COME ON!
LET'S SEE SOME BANANAS AND NUTS!
OH, PERHAPS WE SHOULD
JUST PULL THEIR PANTS OFF.
- HEY, WHAT THE HELL
DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?
THIS IS WHERE WE SHOOT.
- YEAH, WELL,
YOU'VE GOT COMPETITION NOW,
'CAUSE WE'RE MAKING OUR OWN
VIDEO.
- WILL YOU JUST GET OVER IT?
IT'S NUDITY.
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE ASHAMED
OF YOUR BODY
DOESN'T MEAN EVERYBODY
SHOULD BE.
- OH, REALLY?
WELL, LET'S SEE HOW YOU FEEL
ABOUT WHAT YOU'RE PACKING.
- YOU'RE A [bleep] NEVER-NUDE?
- YOU'RE ASKING GIRLS
TO TAKE THEIR TOPS OFF,
AND YOU CAN'T EVEN BE NAKED?
I'VE GOTTA GET THIS.
- LINDSAY, I'VE ALREADY GOT IT.
I'M BACK INTO CUTOFFS.
LINDSAY?
- I DIDN'T SEE YOU
AT THE CONVENTION.
- NO, I WAS IN GERMANY.
I TELECONFERENCED IN.
- OHHH.
- DID YOU GO TO THE SEMINAR
ON CHAFING?
- DR. SCHOENWEISS?
YES.
- THIS IS NEVER GONNA WORK.
THERE'S TOO MANY PEOPLE,
TOO MANY ROOMS.
- MICHAEL, WE CAN'T GIVE UP.
THIS IS IMPORTANT.
BELIEVE ME, I'D RATHER
BE DOWN AT THE BEACH,
HAVING DRINKS,
HOWLING AT CHICKS.
[howls]
- [nearby howling]
- DAD?
- [howls]
OH, MY BOYS.
YES, YOU--YOU CAME FOR ME.
- YEAH, HI, DAD.
UH, GOB'S GONNA GET YOU OUT
OF THOSE HANDCUFFS.
CAN YOU DO IT, PAL?
- ONE HANDCUFF KEY COMING UP.
- GREAT.
- [retching]
- WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
- SWALLOWED A KEY JUST IN CASE
I ENDED UP DOING A SHOW.
- [retching]
- COME ON. THIS IS DISGUSTING.
- I'M DOING THIS FOR YOU.
- THIS CONTINUED FOR SOME TIME,
WHILE MICHAEL SWITCHED OUT
THE COOLERS.
- WHY ARE YOU SWITCHING OUT
THE COOLERS?
- IT BUYS US TIME, DAD.
- WHAT? LIKE A SECOND?
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT, OKAY?
I WILL TELL YOU THIS.
WHEN I GET THIS EVIDENCE
OUT OF HERE,
I'M TURNING IT
RIGHT INTO THE COURT.
- ARE YOU KIDDING?
I DON'T CARE IF THE EVIDENCE
GETS OUT THERE.
IT GETS ME OFF THE HOOK.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
THIS EXONERATES YOU?
- I TOLD YOU BEFORE.
I WAS A PATSY.
I WAS SET UP.
I AM TIRED OF LOOKING GUILTY.
- WELL, THAT'S--THAT'S GREAT.
- [gags]
[clattering]
NOW WHO'S A HORRIBLE MAGICIAN?
- THAT IS A CROWN,
YOU HORSE'S ASS.
- HOW DOES THAT MAKE YOU FEEL?
- AWESOME.
- AND GEORGE MICHAEL CAUGHT UP
WITH MAEBY,
DETERMINED TO SAVE
HER SELF-ESTEEM.
- LOOK, I DON'T WANT
TO RUIN YOUR FUN, YOU KNOW,
BUT I HATE TO SEE GUYS
TREAT YOU LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE BETTER THAN THAT.
TO ME ANYWAY.
YOU'RE--
- AWESOME?
NO, I WAS GONNA SAY
YOU'RE--
YOU'RE LIKE THIS FLOWER,
AND I KNOW IT'S SPRINGTIME,
BUT I JUST--I'D HATE
TO SEE YOU GET PLUCKED
BY SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T EVEN CARE
THAT YOU'RE BLOSSOMING.
- THAT'S WHAT I'VE
BEEN WAITING TO HEAR.
- MAEBY WAS REFERRING
TO THE DIALOGUE,
BUT GEORGE MICHAEL
HAD JUST REDISCOVERED
HIS FEELINGS FOR HIS COUSIN.
- HI, ANN, IT'S--
IT'S GEORGE MICHAEL BLUTH.
UM, WHEN YOU GET BACK
INTO TOWN, WE SHOULD TALK.
[thump]
[crowd applauding]
- CAN I GET YOU
ANYTHING ELSE, MA'AM?
- NO, THANKS.
I HAVE TO GET BACK TO REHAB.
- SHE'S IN REHAB!
[cheering]
- AND SO GEORGE SR. WAS FREE,
AND MICHAEL AND GOB
ABSCONDED WITH THE EVIDENCE.
- ONE HECK OF A TRICK YOU ENDED
UP PULLIN' IN THERE, GOB.
- TRUTHFULLY, THAT WASN'T
PART OF THE ACT.
I WAS ACTUALLY TRYING TO GET
THE KEY TO COME OUT OF MY MOUTH.
- THAT PART WAS VERY SURPRISING,
BUT I'M TALKING ABOUT HOW YOU
HELPED ME GET DAD OUT OF THERE.
THANKS TO YOU, THIS FAMILY
COULD END UP BEING OKAY.
- AND GOB HAD FINALLY OVERCOME
HIS OWN LOW SELF-ESTEEM.
- HEY, AREN'T YOU THAT MAGICIAN
WHO ALWAYS EMBARRASSES HIMSELF?
- NOT ANYMORE.
NOT ANYMORE.
- GOB!
- BUT HE LOST IT,
ALONG WITH
THE EXONERATING EVIDENCE.
- THEY'RE LAUGHING, MICHAEL.
THEY'RE LAUGHING.
- AND THAT'S HOW
YOU NARRATE A STORY.
ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT".
LUCILLE GETS SOME
DISTURBING INFORMATION.
DID YOU GET THE EVIDENCE?
- YES, AND THEN GOB RUINED IT.
AFTER ALL THE TROUBLE WE WENT
THROUGH TO SWITCH COOLERS
WITH THE ONE
FROM THE BANANA STAND.
- THE ONE IN THE FREEZER?
I WAS STORING VERY IMPORTANT
THINGS THERE.
- AND KITTY FINDS
WHAT SHE'S BEEN LOOKING FOR.
- THERE WAS 250 C.C.s OF YOUR
FATHER IN THAT BANANA STAND!
- NO TOUCHING.
- [singing]
SOMEHOW I'M ALWAYS
FINDIN' MYSELF
I'M STUCK
STUCK IN THE SAME PLACE
SAME RULES WITH THE SAME FOOLS
ALWAYS BE PICKIN' ON ME
I'M GONNA BE STICKIN' AROUND
I'M STICKIN' AROUND
THIS TIME
UH