[narrator]
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
[narrator]
MICHAEL BLUTH
WAS WORKING AT HOME WHEN
HE NOTICED SOMETHING UNUSUAL.
[rattling]
- THAT CAN'T BE GOOD.
- OKAY, I CHECKED UNDERNEATH,
AND THERE IS A PROBLEM.
YOU KNOW THIS ISN'T
A REAL HOUSE?
- IT'S A MODEL HOUSE.
- WELL, THE DRAIN PIPES
AREN'T HOOKED UP.
JUST EMPTY UNDER THE HOUSE.
PLUS, THERE'S A LOT OF
BLUE PAINT DOWN THERE.
- AND SOME PIECES OF DENIM?
- YEAH.
- WE'VE GOT A GUY
LIKE THAT HERE.
- WELL, THAT'S WHY YOUR
LIVING ROOM IS SINKING.
AND I THINK THE CITY'S
GONNA HAVE TO RED-TAG IT.
- THE CITY IS SENDING OUT
AN INSPECTOR.
THEY'RE GONNA BE CRAWLING OVER
EVERY INCH OF THIS PLACE.
YOU'RE GOING TO NEED TO LEAVE.
- WHERE THE HELL
DO YOU WANT ME TO GO?
BACK TO YOUR MOTHER'S?
I BELIEVE THERE'S
A FREELOADING LOSER IN MY BED.
- BUSTER JUST LOST A HAND.
HE'S GOING THROUGH A LOT.
- I'M TALKING ABOUT OSCAR.
- OH, YES.
YOUR BROTHER.
I CAN SEE WHY
THAT WOULD BUG YOU.
[narrator]
IN FACT, OSCAR HAD
STAYED WITH LUCILLE PRIMARILY
TO RECONNECT WITH BUSTER,
WHOM HE SECRETLY BELIEVED
TO BE HIS NATURAL SON.
- HEY, UNCLE.
I FEEL SO RESPONSIBLE
FOR THAT.
[narrator]
OSCAR HAD GOTTEN INJURED
ON A SHODDY DEVICE
GEORGE SR. HAD INVENTED...
WHEN HE FORGOT BUSTER
WAS WEARING A PROSTHETIC HAND.
- BUSTER!
THE CORNBALLER!
[both screaming]
[sizzling]
- IT'S MY FATHER'S FAULT!
- MY FAULT?
I WAS TRYING TO KEEP YOU
FROM BURNING YOURSELF,
YOU IDIOT!
I MEAN, YES, YES.
GEORGE SR.
SURE RUSHED THIS TO MARKET.
- THE ONLY REASON SHE LIKES HIM
IS HE HAS HAIR.
AND THE ONLY REASON
HE HAS ANY IS BECAUSE
HE'S NEVER HAD ANY STRESS.
- YEAH?
WELL, YOU COULD SAVE ME
A LOT OF STRESS
IF YOU JUST TURNED YOURSELF IN.
- NO, NEVER.
I CAN'T GO BACK TO THE JOINT.
NO, I CANNOT GO BACK THERE.
[singing]
WHAT COULD BE BETTER
- HEY, MAN!
- TO HOLD THINGS TOGETHER
- YEAH!
[singing]
SO GOOD TO COME CLEAN
- IT'S A HELL-HOLE.
- I FINALLY GOT THE COURT
TO TRY YOU IN ABSENTIA.
WHICH MEANS WE'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO HAVE ANY IDEA WHERE YOU ARE.
SO YOU DON'T
HAVE TO GO TO PRISON,
BUT YOU CAN'T STAY HERE.
- REMEMBER THAT FRENCH MOVIE
WE TRIED TO SNEAK INTO ONCE--
DANGEROUS COUSINS?
- NO, I-- WHY? DID WE--
[stammering]
I DON'T REMEMBER THAT, NO.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL
REMEMBERED VERY WELL.
IN FACT, HE CURRENTLY
HAD A COPY OF THE DVD
HIDDEN IN HIS SOCK DRAWER.
- KIND OF.
WHY DO YOU ASK?
- I GOT PASSES TO THE PREMIERE
OF THE AMERICAN REMAKE.
SUPPOSED TO BE GREAT.
[narrator]
IT WASN'T GREAT,
AND MAEBY KNEW IT.
THE STUDIO AT WHICH SHE'D
FINAGLED A JOB HAD HOPED
TO AVOID CONTROVERSY...
BY ARTLESSLY EXPLAINING
THAT THE TWO LEADS
WEREN'T BIOLOGICAL COUSINS.
[woman on film]
SHUT UP AND KISS ME!
- WHERE IS EVERYBODY?
- THEY'VE BEEN FIRED.
AND YOU GOTTA FIX THIS,
OR YOU'RE GONNA BE FIRED TOO.
CUT IT DOWN
IF YOU HAVE TO.
- BUT IT'S ONLY 71 MINUTES LONG.
AND IT'S ONLY,
LIKE, 63 MINUTES LONG.
SO BRING ANN.
- NO, THAT'S NOT
HER KIND OF THING.
I MEAN, IF IT MAINTAINS
ANY OF THE COMPLEX EROTICISM
OF THE FRENCH ORIGINAL ANYWAY.
I LIKE THE WAY THEY THINK.
[narrator]
AND LATER, AT THE OFFICE,
MICHAEL HAD ANOTHER SURPRISE.
- THIS CAN'T BE GOOD.
- "MICHAEL, IT SADDENS ME
GREATLY TO SAY TO YOU...
"THAT I CAN NO LONGER WORK
AT THE BLUTH COMPANY.
YOU'VE BEEN A GREAT BOSS"--
- I'M SORRY, TOBIAS.
DO YOU WORK HERE?
- DO I WORK--
I DEVELOPED AN EATING DISORDER
BEING YOUR ASSISTANT, MICHAEL.
- I NEVER SAW YOU AT THE DESK.
- WELL, EXCUSE ME
IF I WAS TOO BUSY ON MY KNEES
IN FRONT OF THE TOILET, MICHAEL.
"I HAVE A TREMENDOUS
OPPORTUNITY...
"NOW THAT THE BLUE MAN GROUP
"HAS DROPPED THEIR
CEASE-AND-DESIST...
"AND INVITED ME TO AUDITION
IN LAS VEGAS.
ALSO, I'VE DEVELOPED
SOME ISSUES WITH FOOD"--
- I'M SORRY TO INTERRUPT
ONE MORE TIME.
IS THIS THE REAL
BLUE MAN GROUP THIS TIME?
[narrator]
TOBIAS HAD RECENTLY BEEN
ASKED TO ADDRESS
A GROUP OF DEPRESSED MEN...
WHO HAD BEEN DESCRIBED
OVER THE PHONE AS BLUE.
- I FEEL LIKE
A-- [bleep] IDIOT.
FORTUNATELY, I FOUND
A WONDERFUL CIRCLE OF MEN
TO GET ME THROUGH THAT.
OH, BEFORE I FORGET,
YOUR OLD SECRETARY,
KITTY SANCHEZ, CALLED...
AND WANTED
TO MEET WITH YOU.
I PENCILED HER IN
FOR 4:00 TODAY.
- WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME?
- OH, THIS IS MY FAULT TOO?
EVERYTHING-- NO.
NO! I WILL NOT LET THIS
MAKE ME EAT!
[sobbing]
- SO GET THIS.
TOMORROW I GOTTA
GO ON RECORD AND SAY
I DON'T KNOW WHERE DAD IS.
AND NOW KITTY SANCHEZ
WANTS TO MEET WITH ME.
[narrator]
AND MEETINGS WITH KITTY
HAD NEVER ENDED WELL.
- SAY GOOD-BYE TO THESE.
- SPRING BREAK! WHOO!
- PERHAPS THIS'LL
JOG YOUR MEMORY.
- [Cal]
OH! THEY'RE CROOKED!
- PLUS, DAD WILL NOT
LEAVE THE ATTIC, WHICH MEANS
HE'S GONNA GET CAUGHT,
WHICH MEANS I'M GONNA
GET CAUGHT FOR HIDING HIM.
- WELL, WHY DON'T YOU
GET GOB TO DO
YOUR DIRTY WORK FOR YOU?
SHALL I KNOCK DAD OUT AND
CHAIN HIM TO A PIPE SOMEWHERE?
OR SHOULD I RISK ANOTHER
HERPES OUTBREAK WITH KITTY?
WHICH IS IT THIS TIME?
- DEFINITELY NOT
ONE OF THOSE TWO THINGS.
BUT ARE YOU UPSET
ABOUT SOMETHING, GOB?
- I MADE YOU A THANK-YOU GIFT
LAST WEEK ABOUT WHICH
YOU HAVEN'T SAID WORD ONE.
- COME ON.
YOU ASKED ME FOR $5,000...
SO THAT YOU COULD INVEST
IN A FRANKLIN CD.
NOW, I ASSUMED THAT YOU WERE
TALKING ABOUT THE MUTUAL FUND...
AND NOT A COMPACT DISC
OF YOU SINGING TO YOUR HAND.
[narrator]
GOB HAD RECENTLY MADE
A RECORDING
OF HIS VENTRILOQUISM ACT.
- "FRANKLIN COMES ALIVE."
TAKE ONE.
[narrator]
HE HOPED IT WOULD
BREAK DOWN RACIAL BARRIERS
AND MAYBE BE A CROSSOVER HIT.
- [singing]
IT AIN'T EASY
BEIN' WHITE
BEIN' BROWN
ALL THIS PRESSURE
TO BE BRIGHT
I GOT CHILDREN
ALL OVER TOWN
SOMETIMES--
HEY, WHERE'D THE GUY GO?
I TRIED TO EXPRESS
SOMETHING TO YOU IN
A COUPLE OF THOSE NUMBERS...
AND MAYBE, JUST MAYBE,
HEAL THIS COUNTRY A LITTLE BIT.
BUT YOU, YOU DIDN'T EVEN
BOTHER TO LISTEN TO IT.
- I DID LISTEN TO IT.
I-I-I-I AM LISTENING TO IT.
GOB. HEY.
MAYBE THE REASON
I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING IS 'CAUSE
I DIDN'T WANT TO EMBARRASS YOU.
IT'S MY FAVORITE,
FAVORITE RECORD.
- WELL, THEN YOU--
YOU-- [bleeps] UP.
[sobbing]
BECAUSE I AM SO EMBARRASSED.
- IT'S A GOOD CD.
IT'S A REALLY GOOD CD.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT YOU LOVE IT.
- I LOVE IT SO MUCH.
- OH, GOD.
OH, GOD, LOOK AT US.
CRYING LIKE
A COUPLE OF GIRLS.
- AW, YOU'RE
THE ONLY ONE CRYING.
BUT I LOVE THE MUSIC.
- AND THE CARD
WITH YOUR FACE ON IT?
- AND THE HEALING.
- HOME RUN!
WE'LL DO YOUR DIRTY WORK
FOR YOU, MIKEY.
YOU LEAVE THE ROUGH STUFF
TO FRANKLIN AND ME.
- NOW I GOTTA LISTEN TO THAT CD.
- HI, DAD.
- RIGHT.
- YOU REMEMBER FRANKLIN.
- HEY, FRANKLIN.
- MY MAN!
HOW 'BOUT SOME TONGUE?
- WHA-- OH--
[narrator]
BUT FRANKLIN
DIDN'T WANT TO KISS AT ALL.
GOB HAD SOAKED
THE PUPPET'S MOUTH IN ETHER.
AND DOWNSTAIRS, TOBIAS SHARED
HIS GOOD NEWS WITH LINDSAY.
[water running]
- "...ONCE IN A LIFETIME."
- TOBIAS, I AM NOT UPROOTING
MY LIFE AND MOVING TO VEGAS.
MAYBE THIS IS A SIGN THAT
OUR RELATIONSHIP ISN'T WORKING,
AND WE SHOULD SPLIT AGAIN.
- WAIT A SECOND.
I THOUGHT WE WERE SPLIT UP,
AND THIS WOULD
BRING US BACK TOGETHER.
- WELL, MAYBE THE FACT
THAT WE DON'T KNOW
IF WE'RE TOGETHER OR NOT...
IS A SIGN
THAT WE SHOULD SPLIT AGAIN.
- OR STAY SPLIT UP.
OKAY, FORGET ABOUT VEGAS.
WE'LL STAY HERE
AND GET BACK TOGETHER.
OR STAY TOGETHER AND EITHER
REKINDLE OR FAN THIS FIRE.
[house creaking]
[narrator]
AND SOON, GOB WAS
ON HIS WAY TO DUMP HIS FATHER
ON THE POLICE STATION STEPS.
- DO YOU FORGIVE ME?
[narrator]
AND HE DECIDED TO
LET HIMSELF OFF THE HOOK
USING HIS VENTRILOQUIST SKILL.
- [imitating George Sr.]
I CHERISH YOU, GOB.
COME HERE AND GIVE ME A KISS.
I'M DRIVING, DAD.
[as George Sr.]
NOW!
[narrator]
IT WAS WEIRD.
[kiss]
AND THAT'S WHEN GOB
NOTICED THE CD AND CARD
THAT HE'D MADE FOR MICHAEL.
- IT'S NOT EVEN OPEN.
MICHAEL!
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, MICHAEL'S
MEETING WITH KITTY WASN'T
AS DISTRESSING AS HE'D THOUGHT.
- THE PROGRAM HAS
CHANGED MY LIFE.
AND I HAVE A SPONSOR NOW.
[whispers]
HE'S FAMOUS.
- THAT'S GREAT.
- I CAN'T TELL YOU
WHO HE IS.
BUT LET'S JUST SAY THAT HE WAS
ON NIGHT COURT.
- WELL, YOU LOOK GREAT.
- I CAN TELL YOU WHO IT'S NOT.
IT'S NOT BULL.
IT'S NOT HARRY ANDERSON.
- I GOT IT.
- HE'S WHITE.
- I KNOW WHO IT IS.
- WHAT HAPPENS IS, WHEN I DON'T
HAVE A MAN IN MY LIFE,
I TEND TO GO A LITTLE CRAZY.
- MM-HMM.
- BUT I'M KEEPING IT
TOGETHER NOW.
AND I WANTED TO TELL YOU
I'M NOT GONNA TRY
TO HURT YOU GUYS ANYMORE.
- DON'T SUPPOSE I CAN
GET THAT IN WRITING.
- YOU DID TRY TO BLOW ME UP.
- SORRY ABOUT THAT.
- JUST DON'T PISS ME OFF AGAIN.
[cackles]
- [chuckling]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
- "OFTENTIMES THE HEART
ACTS WITHOUT CONSULTING
THE HEAD, AND THUSLY"--
OH, I SEE YOU WASTED NO TIME
IN FILLING MY SEAT HOLE.
- OH, NO, NO.
I JUST CAME BY SO THAT YOU COULD
SAY GOOD-BYE TO THESE.
- OH, NO, NO, NO, NO.
- IT'S THE LAST TIME YOU'RE
GOING TO BE SEEING THESE.
- HOW IRONIC.
I JUST FOUND OUT I'M STAYING.
WILL YOU TAKE THESE BACK?
- OKAY, LET'S JUST ALL
PUT OUR TOPS DOWN.
JUST PUT 'EM ON DOWN.
YOU'RE NOT GOIN' TO VEGAS?
- SADLY, MY WIFE
SAID NO TO MY DREAM.
SO I SHALL CONTINUE TO TOIL
THROUGH THIS WAKING LIFE.
- WOW, YOU ARE SO REAL.
WHY CAN'T I MEET
SOMEONE LIKE YOU?
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL DECIDED
THAT HE BETTER KEEP KITTY
OCCUPIED WITH A MAN.
AT LEAST
UNTIL AFTER HIS MEETING.
- HEY, GANG, I GOT AN IDEA.
TOBIAS, WHY DON'T YOU TAKE KITTY
OUT FOR THE AFTERNOON?
- [stammering]
HUH?
- ARE YOU TRYING TO SET UP
YOUR FORMER ASSISTANT
WITH YOUR CURRENT ASSISTANT?
WHAT A GREAT IDEA FOR
A HUGH GRANT-JULIA ROBERTS
TYPE MOVIE.
- I RECENTLY HEARD THAT
THE ACTOR,
JOHN LARROQUETTE, WAS LOOKING
FOR A MEATY CHARACTER PIECE.
[narrator]
AND SO, FREE OF OBSTACLES,
MICHAEL PREPARED
TO SIGN THE AFFIDAVIT...
MAINTAINING HE HAD NO IDEA
WHERE HIS FATHER WAS.
- YOU HAVE NOT BEEN
IN CONTACT WITH HIM.
ARE YOU PREPARED TO DO THAT?
OFFICERS!
MICHAEL, THESE MEN ARE HERE--
JUST A LITTLE BIT EARLY--
BECAUSE WE HAVE
PHOTOGRAPHIC EVIDENCE...
WHICH DISCREDITS
THE AFFIDAVIT YOU JUST SIGNED.
- ARE THOSE BALLS?
'CAUSE THE LAST TIME WE WERE
HERE, THEY WERE BALLS.
- THESE ARE NOT BALLS.
THIS WAS TAKEN
WITH A TRAFFIC CAMERA.
IT SHOWS YOU
IN YOUR CAR WITH YOUR FATHER
WITHIN THE LAST 24 HOURS.
- I WISH THEY WERE BALLS.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS IN POLICE CUSTODY...
AFTER A PHOTO OF HIM HELPING
HIS FATHER ESCAPE HAD TURNED UP.
- DID YOU SEE THAT PICTURE?
THAT'S YOU, RIGHT?
WERE YOU HOLDIN' UP
A PHOTO OF ME OR SOMETHIN'?
- OF COURSE
YOU DON'T RECOGNIZE IT.
IT'S THE CARD FROM THE CD
YOU DIDN'T EVEN OPEN.
- YOU FOUND THAT, DID YOU?
- RIGHT BETWEEN THE GEARBOX
AND THE "PULL BACK
FROM AIRCRAFT" LEVER.
SO THIS IS HOW YOU REPAY ME
FOR HOW I REPAY YOU?
- I ACTUALLY DID NOT GET
A CHANCE TO LISTEN TO IT YET.
PROBABLY SHOULD'VE TOLD YOU,
BUT I DIDN'T WANT
TO HURT YOUR FEELINGS.
- OH, YOU'RE SO SENSITIVE.
JUST LIKE WHEN YOU WHIPPED UP
THOSE TEARS TALKING ABOUT
HOW MUCH YOU LOVED IT.
- I WILL LISTEN TO IT,
I PROMISE.
BUT I'M IN A LOT OF
TROUBLE HERE. WHERE IS DAD?
- I'VE GOT HIM STASHED AWAY
SOMEWHERE SAFE NOW.
- GET HIM, QUICKLY, OTHERWISE
I'M GONNA BE STUCK IN HERE.
- GOOD!
I HOPE YOU ROT IN HERE!
- WHAT--
- AND GUESS WHAT ELSE?
DAD KISSED ME.
- HOW?
HE LOOKED PRETTY UNCONSCIOUS
IN THAT PICTURE.
- I DIDN'T SAY
HE WAS TOTALLY INTO IT.
[narrator]
AND GEORGE MICHAEL
TRIED TO BREAK UP WITH ANN.
- I CAN'T GO OUT TOMORROW NIGHT,
'CAUSE THERE'S THIS
MOVIE PREMIERE AT--
IT'S KINDA RACY, BUT--
- OH, THE COUSIN ONE?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I WAS JUST GONNA ASK YOU TO GO.
- YOU WANT TO SEE THAT?
- NO, I WANT TO GET THE WHOLE
CHURCH GROUP TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA
PICKET THOSE BASTARDS.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL HAD ONLY
HEARD ANN SWEAR ONCE BEFORE...
WHEN HE JOINED SOME OF
HER YOUTH GROUP TO PROTEST
THE HOME OF MARC CHERRY,
EXECUTIVE PRODUCER
OF THE HIT SHOW
DESPERATE HOUSEWIVES.
- IT'S A SATIRE!
- THERE'S NOTHING FUNNY
ABOUT FORNICATION!
- THE BASTARD SAW US!
[narrator]
AND THE PROMISE OF ANOTHER KISS
WAS TOO ENTICING TO TURN DOWN.
- WELL, YES.
THE BASTARDS.
[narrator]
OSCAR, MEANWHILE,
CHECKED IN ON BUSTER.
- [gasps]
BUSTER! BUSTER! BE CAREFUL!
- IT'S NOT A REAL HAND,
REMEMBER?
- I'M SO FORGETFUL.
I HOPE YOU DON'T
GET THAT FROM ME.
- GET THAT FROM YOU?
DO YOU FEEL OKAY?
[sizzling]
- [screams]
JUST FORGET IT!
I WANTED TO SHARE
MY POP SECRET WITH YOU.
OH, BUT FORGET IT!
- POP SECRET?
POP SE--
IS OSCAR MY REAL FATHER?
[narrator]
LUCILLE, MEANWHILE,
WAS ON THE PHONE WITH MICHAEL.
THEY'RE KEEPING ME OVERNIGHT.
COULD YOU TELL MY SON
I'M ON A BUSINESS TRIP?
- WHY CAN'T THE GIRL
AT WORK DO IT?
- TOBIAS?
I SENT HIM ON A DATE WITH KITTY
TO KEEP HER OFF OUR BACKS.
- YOU BETTER HOPE
LINDSAY DOESN'T FIND OUT.
SHE'LL BE DEVASTATED.
- FIND OUT WHAT?
- YOUR HUSBAND'S DATING
KITTY THE WHORE.
- HE IS?
THAT'S-- THAT'S HORRIBLE.
- DO I KNOW MY DAUGHTER?
SHE ONLY WANTS
WHAT SHE CAN'T HAVE.
SINCE YOU'RE
DEVASTATING PEOPLE,
TELL GOB I'LL BE
TELLING THE COPS
IT WAS HIM IN THE TRUCK,
SO HE'LL BE JOINING ME HERE.
I'VE GOT A NICE, HARD COT
WITH HIS NAME ON IT.
- YOU'D DO THAT
TO YOUR OWN BROTHER?
- I SAID "COT."
- WHERE'S MOTHER?
YOU LIED TO ME.
YOU SAID MY FATHER WAS
MY FATHER, BUT MY UNCLE IS
MY FATHER.
MY FATHER IS MY UNCLE!
[narrator]
AT THAT MOMENT,
THE GUARDS PLAYED A CD
THEY'D RECENTLY CONFISCATED.
[Gob]
NOW I GOT A SPECIAL
THANK YOU TO THE BROTHER
WHO MADE THIS HAPPEN.
- IS THAT FRANKLIN?
- [singing]
YEAH, I WOULD FIGHT FOR YOU
I'D LIE FOR YOU
WALK THE WIRE
FOR YOU
YEAH
I'D DIE FOR YOU
[narrator]
MICHAEL REALIZED THAT HE COULD
NEVER TURN HIS BROTHER IN.
[Gob]
MICHAEL!
[singing]
YOU KNOW IT'S TRUE
[narrator]
GOB, MEANWHILE,
WAS HAVING A SIMILAR EPIPHANY.
- EVERYTHING I DO
I DO IT FOR YOU
BARRY, IT'S GOB.
TELL MICHAEL NOT TO TESTIFY.
I'M BRINGING IN DAD.
[singing on headset]
EVERYTHING I DO NOW
FRANKLIN.
[british accent]
YOU'VE RUINED THE ACT, GOB.
[narrator]
AND LUCILLE CONFRONTED OSCAR.
- YOU TOLD HIM
YOU WERE HIS FATHER?
- I DID NO SUCH THING!
- YOU'RE HIGH!
- YOU'RE DRUNK!
- NOT THIS TIME.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF YOU.
SO SAY GOOD-BYE TO THESE,
BECAUSE IT'S THE LAST TIME--
[narrator]
AND ANN IN A PROTEST
AT THE THEATER.
- GEORGE MICHAEL?
ARE YOU PROTESTING THIS?
- THIS ISN'T THE LINE?
- YES, HE IS
PROTESTING THIS.
HE EVEN HELPED ME
MAKE THE SIGNS.
- WELL, ONLY MINE
AND THE ONE THAT SAYS,
"THIS IS A TRICKY, GRAY AREA."
- WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
PROTESTING?
- IT'S A DISGUSTING MOVIE...
ABOUT COUSINS
WHO ARE INTO EACH OTHER.
- ARE THERE ANY MORE SEATS?
- YEAH.
IT'S THE BEST 52 MINUTES
YOU'LL SPEND ALL DAY.
- OH, NO.
WE'RE MAKING IT WORSE.
PREPARE TO BE SWALLOWED
INTO THE DEPTHS OF HELL!
- I GUESS THAT MEANS NO KISS?
- I'M NOT REALLY
IN THE MOOD FOR A KISS.
THIS ISN'T MARC CHERRY'S HOUSE.
- WHERE'S YOUR DAD?
- I DON'T KNOW. I JUST GOT HERE.
- OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
MOTHER TOLD ME
HE WENT TO JAIL.
I'M SO MAD AT HER.
[creaking]
GUESS WHO I JUST FOUND OUT
MY FATHER IS?
- JAIL?
- OSCAR!
HE DIDN'T MEAN TO TELL ME,
BUT I FIGURED IT OUT.
- NO, I MEAN, MY DAD IS IN JAIL?
- I WOULDN'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
BARRY'S VERY GOOD.
I'M GOING TO TAKE A LONG SHOW.
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO SMELL
LIKE MOTHER ANYMORE.
- I DON'T THINK WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO SHOWER RIGHT NOW, BUS--
- TOBIAS BACK YET?
- NO.
- OH, MY GOD.
HE'S REALLY OUT WITH HER.
- ARE YOU DRUNK?
- NOT ENOUGH.
I PUSHED HIM
RIGHT INTO SOMEONE ELSE'S
SKANKY, BONY ARMS.
WELL, LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
YOU HAVE TO GRAB LOVE
WHILE YOU HAVE IT.
DON'T LET IT GET AWAY.
- OH, THERE YOU ARE.
- OH, MAEBY, EVERYTHING'S FINE.
YOUR DADDY'S JUST OUT.
YEAH, WE'RE DOING GREAT.
MOMMY'S GONNA TAKE A BATH
WITH A BOTTLE OF WINE.
- I DON'T KNOW IF
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO USE--
- SO GET THIS.
ALL THE PRESS ACTUALLY
MADE THE PREMIERE A HIT.
THERE'S LINES FOR THE NEXT SHOW.
THANKS, BUDDY.
HEY, LOOK AT THAT.
WE DIDN'T
GET SWALLOWED UP INTO HELL.
[chuckles]
[narrator]
AND THAT'S WHEN GEORGE MICHAEL
FINALLY GOT CLOSE TO MAEBY,
WHO, BY THE WAY, MIGHT NOT
BE HIS BIOLOGICAL COUSIN.
JUST THEN, GOB CAME HOME
TO RETRIEVE HIS FATHER
FROM WHERE HE'D STASHED HIM.
- DAD'S GONNA BE CRUSHED.
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL HIM!
[narrator]
BUT GOB WAS REFERRING
TO HIS OWN FATHER...
WHO HE HAD HIDDEN
UNDER THE HOUSE.
- UH-OH.
[narrator]
GOB HAD HIDDEN
HIS FATHER UNDER A HOUSE
THAT HAD JUST COLLAPSED.
- CHILDREN, YOU'RE SMALL.
CRAWL UNDER THERE.
- WE DON'T WANT TO GO
UNDER THERE.
- HE'S NOT UNDER THERE.
HE GOT AWAY.
THANK GOD.
[narrator]
BUT THEN GOB REMEMBERED
THAT THIS MEANT MICHAEL
WOULD HAVE TO GO TO PRISON.
- WE--
- I--
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL AND BARRY
MADE THEIR WAY
TO THE ARRAIGNMENT.
- GOB IS BRINGING YOUR FATHER.
EVERYTHING IS GOING TO
WORK OUT FINE.
- I WISH THEY'D HURRY UP.
BUT I GOTTA TELL YOU,
I AM A LITTLE TORN.
MY FATHER, HE HAS CREATED
A LOT OF PROBLEMS
FOR THE FAMILY...
AND BY STAYING IN THE ATTIC
HE WAS INSURING I WOULD
GO TO JAIL WITH HIM, BUT--
WELL, MAYBE
I'M NOT SO TORN.
- MICHAEL. BARRY.
- HEY, GOB.
WHERE'S DAD?
- GREAT NEWS.
DAD WASN'T CRUSHED TO DEATH.
- WAS THERE RISK OF THAT?
- YES.
WELL, I HANDCUFFED HIM
UNDER THE HOUSE.
BUT HE GOT FREE--
THE PIPES I CHAINED HIM TO
WEREN'T CONNECTED TO ANYTHING.
- OH, I'M NOT PREPARED
FOR THIS CASE.
- ARE YOU INSANE?
- NO "THANK YOU" FOR TRYING?
- I'M SICK OF YOU NEEDING
CONSTANT VALIDATION
FOR SCREWING UP.
LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
I'M GONNA TELL THEM
IT WAS YOU IN THE STAIR CAR.
- WELL, LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
FIRST, I'M GONNA BEAT
THE CRAP OUT OF YOU,
THEN I'M GONNA CALL
AN AMBULANCE.
THEN KNOWING YOU,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO WAIT
FOR SOME KIND OF AN APOLOGY.
[grunts]
- COME HERE!
[narrator]
AS THE BOYS SET
TO ONCE AGAIN FIGHTING
IN FRONT OF THE COURTHOUSE--
- STOP IT! STOP IT!
[narrator]
THE FAMILY BEGAN TO SHOW UP
FOR THE ARRAIGNMENT.
- I KNOW YOU'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF SOMETHING, BUT I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T WORK FOR YOU TODAY.
I'M GOING TO VEGAS WITH KITTY.
[narrator]
BUT LINDSAY WASN'T ABOUT TO
LOSE HER MAN WITHOUT A FIGHT.
- OVER MY DEAD BODY!
- [Tobias]
OH, MY--
- HEY! HEY! I SAID--
I SAID ENOUGH!
NOW, STOP IT.
I AM SO TIRED
OF THIS FAMILY FIGHTING.
THE ANGER ENDS NOW.
YOU'RE BROTHERS, AND BROTHERS
STICK TOGETHER NO MATTER WHAT.
FAMILIES STICK TOGETHER.
I HAVE TORN THIS FAMILY APART
WITH MY LIES AND MY COWARDICE,
BUT THAT COMES
TO AN END NOW.
SO I'M TURNING MYSELF IN.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO COME AND
VISIT ME IN PRISON THIS TIME.
'CAUSE YOU DESERVE OSCAR NOW.
- TOBIAS, I ACTUALLY
FOUGHT FOR YOU.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
[chuckles]
I'M GOING TO VEGAS WITH KITTY.
- HUH?
- OH, GEORGE,
I'VE LOST YOU AGAIN.
- TAKE BACK OSCAR, MOTHER.
- I THINK I LOST HIM TOO.
[narrator]
IN FACT, OSCAR
WAS ON HIS WAY OUT OF TOWN...
WHEN HE WAS
APPROACHED BY GEORGE SR.,
WHO HAD JUST ESCAPED
FROM UNDER THE HOUSE.
- I WANT YOU TO TURN ME IN
SO YOU CAN GET THE REWARD,
TAKE CARE OF THE FAMILY.
- WHY WOULD YOU DO THAT
FOR ME?
- BECAUSE WE'RE BROTHERS.
[narrator]
LATER, WHILE GEORGE SR.
WAS SHAVING HIS UNCONSCIOUS
BROTHER'S HEAD,
HE WONDERED WHETHER
THERE REALLY WAS A REWARD,
AND IF HE COULD GET IT.
BUT THERE WAS NO TIME,
AND GETTING EVEN
WITH HIS BROTHER
WAS REWARD ENOUGH.
SO IT WAS OSCAR
WHO WAS GOING TO BE SPENDING
A LITTLE TIME ALONE IN PRISON.
- I GUESS DAD
FINALLY CAME THROUGH FOR US.
HE ACTUALLY MADE A SACRIFICE.
ALTHOUGH WHO KNOWS
WHAT HE'S UP TO.
WE SHOULD JUST STAY AWAY
FROM HIM, LET HIM HAVE
A LITTLE TIME ALONE IN PRISON.
HE IS RIGHT
ABOUT ONE THING, THOUGH.
WE'RE BROTHERS.
WE SHOULDN'T BE FIGHTING.
WE CANNOT AFFORD
TO LOSE EACH OTHER.
- I CAN'T.
I ALREADY LOST
A BROTHER TODAY.
- FRANKLIN?
- WELL, I DIDN'T LOSE HIM.
BUT HE'S ALL PUCKERED AND WHITE.
- ON THE PLUS SIDE,
YOU CAN TAKE HIM TO LUNCH
AT THE CLUB NOW.
- THAT'S THE KIND OF JOKE
HE WOULD HAVE LOVED.
- OH, MAN!
[sighs]
- [singing]
YOU KNOW IT'S TRUE
EVERYTHING I DO
- PLEASE DON'T DO THIS.
- I DO IT FOR YOU
- ALL RIGHT.
[grunting]
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT SEASON
OF ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
- I BURNED THEM
ON A CORNBALLER.
[narrator]
OSCAR, ROBBED OF
HIS FINGERPRINTS, HAS DIFFICUY
PROVING HIS IDENTITY,
- MY HAIR'S GONNA GROW BACK.
YOU'LL SEE.
[narrator]
TOBIAS AND KITTY GO TO VEGAS,
ONLY TO FIND THAT HIS DREAM JOB
HAS BEEN FILLED.
- YOU FOUND SOMEONE ALREADY?
- JUST CAME OUT OF NOWHERE,
THIS GUY.
AND THE GREAT THING IS,
HE'S NEVER OUT OF CHARACTER.
[narrator]
AND GEORGE SR.
TURNS OUT TO BE RIGHT
ABOUT THE EFFECTS OF STRESS.
- WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME?
WHY WON'T IT GROW BACK?