narrator: NOW THE STORY OF A
WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL BLUTH BEGAN HIS DAY
WITH SOMETHING HE'D NEVER SEEN
BEFORE.
TV announcer: I'M HEARING GOOD
THINGS ABOUT THE BLUTH COMPANY.
narrator: GOOD NEWS ABOUT HIS
FAMILY'S HOUSING BUSINESS.
TV announcer:
OLD MAN BLUTH'S IN JAIL.
I THINK HIS SON IS
RUNNING THE COMPANY.
DOESN'T SEEM LIKE
A TOTAL MORON TO ME.
I'VE HAD THIS THING AS A
TRIPLE SELL,
AND I AM UPGRADING
IT RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW.
I THINK THIS THING COULD EVEN
GO AS HIGH AS A "DON'T BUY."
[bell rings]
- DON'T BUY! HUH?
MOM, DID YOU SEE THAT?
TV announcer:
DON'T BUY BLUTH!
- YOU BUILD A HOUSE THAT'S GOOD,
PEOPLE ARE GONNA WANNA COME--
THIS SINKHOLE SPREAD
A LITTLE BIT MORE LAST NIGHT?
ANYWAY, I'M GONNA GO TO THE
PRISON.
I'M GONNA TELL DAD
ABOUT THIS NEWS.
- I THOUGHT YOU SAID
WE SHOULDN'T VISIT HIM.
- VISIT, NO.
GLOAT, YES.
I'VE WORKED VERY, VERY HARD
FOR THIS.
I SOLD THE CABIN
PROPERTY TO KEEP US AFLOAT.
I HAVEN'T HAD ANY TIME
TO SPEND WITH MY SON.
- WELL, NOW YOU CAN SPEND TIME
WITH MY SON.
I WANT YOUR BROTHER
BUSTER TO COME LIVE WITH YOU.
AND IT'S NOT BECAUSE HE HAS THAT
HORRIBLE HOOK FOR A HAND NOW.
IT'S THE SNORING.
LISTEN TO THIS.
BUSTER'S SNORING.
WEDNESDAY NIGHT.
[Buster snoring]
IT'S DRIVING ME CRA--
YOU WON'T EVEN KNOW
HE'S HERE.
- YOU SEEM MORE VILLAINOUS
THAN USUAL, MOM.
ARE YOU SOBER?
- MICHAEL, IT'S 8:00 A.M.
- SO, IT'S NOT THAT.
- I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE IT'S BECAUSE I WENT OFF
MY POSTPARTUM MEDICATION.
- YOU WERE STILL TAKING THAT?
YOU HAD BUSTER 32 YEARS AGO.
- AND THAT'S HOW LONG
I'VE BEEN DEPRESSED ABOUT HIM.
ACTUALLY, I DID GO OFF IT IN
THE EARLY '90S,
BUT I DIDN'T
LIKE WHAT HAPPENED TO ME.
TV announcer: CLAIMING SHE COULD
TAKE IT NO MORE,
THE YOUNG MOTHER
RELEASED THE EMERGENCY BRAKE,
ALLOWING HER CAR TO ROLL
BACKWARDS INTO THE NEARBY LAKE.
- GOOD FOR HER.
I MUST HAVE GAINED
THREE POUNDS.
- WHY DID YOU GO OFF THEM
THIS TIME?
- WELL, APPARENTLY,
MOOD-ALTERING MEDICATION
LEADS TO STREET DRUGS.
THAT'S WHAT THIS VERY HANDSOME
YOUNG DOCTOR SAID
ON THE TODAY SHOW.
- THAT WAS TOM CRUISE,
THE ACTOR.
- THEY SAID HE WAS
SOME KIND OF SCIENTIST.
- MAYBE YOU SHOULD GET AWAY
FROM BUSTER.
WHY DON'T YOU GO UP
TO THE CABIN IN THE WOODS.
- I THOUGHT YOU SAID WE SOLD IT.
- WE SOLD THE PROPERTY.
I WORKED IT OUT SO WE COULD
RELOCATE THE CABIN,
BUT IT IS GONNA BE UP IN
TAHOE
FOR ANOTHER COUPLE
OF DAYS.
MAYBE YOU CAN
TAKE A DATE UP THERE.
- HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO FIND
SOMEONE
WILLING TO GO INTO THAT MUSTY
OLD CLAPTRAP?
- THE CABIN.
YES.
THAT WOULD BE DIFFICULT TOO.
PLEASE GET BACK ON THE MEDS,
MOM.
WE MISS THE OLD, OLD YOU.
- I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THAT WE HAD A CABIN.
- AH--[bleeps].
WELL, FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH, GOB,
I'VE NEVER ACTUALLY BEEN THERE.
narrator: ALTHOUGH HE'D OFTEN
BEEN PROMISED.
- HEY, PAL. SOMETHING'S COME UP.
THIS NICE YOUNG LADY HAS LOST
HER PUPPY
AND YOUR DAD'S
GOT TO HELP HER FIND HIM.
- OH, BAD NEWS, BUDDY.
THIS YOUNG LADY'S DAD IS SICK,
AND I'M TAKING HER
TO THE HOSPITAL.
COME ON. YOU'RE OLD ENOUGH
TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
I'M NAILING THIS BROAD.
- PARDON ME IF I DON'T
BURST INTO TEARS, MICHAEL,
BUT AT LEAST HE
PROMISED TO TAKE YOU.
HE JUST LET ME BLINDLY
ENJOY MY CHILDHOOD.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW THERE WAS A
CABIN HE WASN'T TAKING ME TO.
- MMM.
MINE'S SADDER.
- I DON'T SEE
YOU CRYING, ROBOT!
YOU TASTE THESE TEARS.
TASTE MY SAD, MICHAEL.
- NO. NOT GONNA
LICK YOUR EYE, OKAY.
- WELL, I WILL TELL
YOU THIS, MICHAEL.
I DON'T HAVE A SON.
narrator: HE DOES.
BUT IF I EVER DO,
I'M EITHER GONNA TAKE HIM
TO THE CABIN IN THE WOODS,
OR I'M GONNA PROMISE TO TAKE HIM
AND THEN NOT TAKE HIM.
BUT THE ONE THING
THAT I WILL NEVER DO...
IS NOT TELL HIM THAT I'M TAKING
HIM TO A CABIN IN THE WOODS,
AND THEN NOT TAKE HIM.
narrator:
GOB WAS GROWING UP.
- WELL, THE CABIN IN THE WOODS
IS GONNA BE STACKED UP
NEXT TO OUR CARPORT.
BUT MAYBE WE SHOULD HEAD UP
THERE TONIGHT, HUH?
ONE...FIRST TIME.
- TASTE THE HAPPY, MICHAEL.
- OH, NO.
[grunts]
- TASTE IT.
- TASTES KIND OF LIKE SAD.
narrator: MICHAEL SET OFF
TO PRISON
TO TELL OFF HIS FATHER
WHEN HE DISCOVERED HIS SON.
- GEORGE MICHAEL?
- DAD, HEY.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I DIDN'T WANNA MISS
YOU BECAUSE
YOU'VE BEEN LEAVING SO EARLY
LATELY.
- YOU SLEPT OUT HERE
TO SEE ME?
narrator: MICHAEL HAD NEVER BEEN
SO TOUCHED
BY SOMETHING HIS SON HAD SAID.
BUT IT WASN'T TRUE.
HE WAS HIDING FROM HIS COUSIN
AFTER AN AWKWARD INCIDENT.
[loud rumbling]
THEY'D SINCE BEEN TRYING
TO AVOID EACH OTHER,
WHICH WAS DIFFICULT, CONSIDERING
THEY SHARED A BUNK BED.
- OH, HI.
- HI.
I'M OFF TO THE CAR.
- I'LL BE IN
THE CRAWL SPACE.
- TELL YOU WHAT, HOW WOULD YOU
LIKE TO HEAD UP TO THE CABIN?
- CAN YOU AFFORD TO SKIP WORK?
- I THINK THE PRESIDENT
OF A "DON'T BUY" COMPANY
CAN AFFORD TO TAKE A DAY OFF.
- WE'RE UP FROM "SELL"?
IT'S HAPPENING, ISN'T IT?
- IT'S REALLY HAPPENING.
IT'S TIME FOR US TO START
CREATING SOME MEMORIES.
THERE'S BEEN ENOUGH
DISAPPOINTMENT IN THIS FAMILY.
[clattering]
- THERE'S ONLY ONE SLEEPING BAG,
SO WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO DOUBLE UP.
PIGS IN A BLANKET!
- SORRY, PAL.
SOMETHING CAME UP.
- IT IS WORSE TO KNOW.
narrator: GOB WAS GETTING LIFE
LESSONS ALL OVER THE PLACE.
AND MICHAEL BROKE
A TWO-MONTH SILENCE
AND WENT TO VISIT HIS FATHER.
- YOU CAME!
SOMEONE CAME!
- ONLY TO TELL YOU THAT THE
COMPANY IS BACK ON TRACK AND
IT'S BECAUSE YOU'RE BEHIND BARS.
AND NOW I GET TO DO WITH MY SON
WHAT YOU NEVER DID WITH ME.
I'M TAKING HIM TO THE CABIN.
- SCAR!
AND EVERY NIGHT--
- I'M SCARRED TOO, BUT MY SON
IS NOT GOING TO BE.
- AND THEY COVER IT WITH SOAP,
AND YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO THANK THEM.
- SO THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL I CAME TO SAY.
- LIKE THEY'RE
DOING YOU A FAVOR!
- ANYTHING YOU'D LIKE FOR ME
TO PASS ON TO THE FAMILY?
- I'M YOUR UNCLE!
I'M YOUR DAD'S
TWIN BROTHER!
I'M OSCAR!
HE SWITCHED ON ME.
NO ONE BELIEVES ME.
narrator:
UNFORTUNATELY FOR OSCAR,
"YOU'VE GOT THE WRONG TWIN"
WAS A VERY POPULAR ALIBI.
- YOU'VE SIMPLY GOT
THE WRONG TWIN.
- WE'RE QUADRUPLETS.
YOU'VE GOT THE WRONG TWO.
- WE'RE LARRY AND DAVE.
- YOU WANT CURTIS AND JEFF.
- I EVEN STARTED A WEB SITE--
IMOSCAR.COM.
I'M INNOCENT, MICHAEL.
IMOSCAR.COM!
- NO, NO, DON'T BUY IT.
I'M TAKING MY SON TO THE CABIN,
AND THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN SAY
TO MAKE ME BELIEVE THAT
YOU ARE NOT MY FATHER.
- I UNDERSTAND.
YOUR CHILD COMES FIRST.
- OH, MY GOD, YOU'RE OSCAR.
- DOT COM.
narrator: SO MICHAEL
RETURNED TO THE OFFICE
TO TRY AND FREE HIS UNCLE.
- DON'T BUY! DON'T BUY!
DON'T BUY!
narrator:
WHEN HE REALIZED HOW MUCH
THAT FREEDOM WOULD COST HIS
EMPLOYEES.
- DON'T BUY!
WE DID IT, MIKEY.
WE'RE SUPER RICH AGAIN.
AND I'M GONNA BUY A CAR.
THE VOLVO.
- LINDSAY, YOU'RE NOT GONNA
START SPENDING MONEY.
AND THIS IS NOT A VOL-VO.
- OH, THAT'S FROM SITTING
ON THE COPIER.
- LINDSAY, NO--
- MICHAEL, I'VE GOT NOTHING.
MY HUSBAND DUMPED ME AND
RAN OFF TO VEGAS WITH KITTY.
THAT BLEACHED
BLONDE WHORE.
- HE'S DEFINITELY GOT A TYPE.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE HE LEFT ME.
I MEAN, THIS AND THESE
AND THIS!
- THAT'S THE CAR.
- OH.
THIS.
- GLAD I DIDN'T SPRING FOR
COLOR.
LINDSAY, THE ONLY REASON YOU
WANT TOBIAS
IS BECAUSE YOU CAN'T HAVE HIM.
AND THE SECOND THAT YOU
CAN HAVE SOMETHING,
ALL OF A SUDDEN
YOU DON'T WANT IT.
- THAT'S NOT WHO I AM, MICHAEL.
- NO? ALL RIGHT,
MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
GET YOU THIS CAR.
- I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S SO BOXY.
- GOB.
- OH, MICHAEL.
HOW'S DAD?
- UH, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S OSCAR WHO'S IN PRISON.
IF I LET HIM OUT, PEOPLE
WILL KNOW DAD IS FREE,
AND THOSE PEOPLE OUT THERE
WILL END UP PAYING FOR IT.
DAD HASN'T, UH, TRIED
TO CONTACT YOU, HAS HE?
- [scoffs] LIKE I'D EVER HEAR
FROM THAT SON OF A BITCH.
narrator: EARLIER THAT DAY,
GOB RECEIVED A LETTER
FROM A GROUP...
THAT REUNITED ABANDONED SONS
WITH THEIR FATHERS, CALLED SAD.
- FATHER-SON REUNION?
BUT DAD'S STILL IN PRISON.
narrator: BUT NOW THE LETTER
MADE SENSE.
- THAT SON OF A BITCH.
- LAW OFFICES
OF BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
- HI, IT'S MICHAEL BLUTH
FOR BARRY.
- BARRY WENT TO RENO
TO SEE YOUR FATHER.
- RENO? HE SAID HE'S BEEN
VISITING MY FATHER IN PRISON.
- YEAH.
BARRY SAYS A LOT OF THINGS
HE DOESN'T MEAN.
- WELL, I GUESS I'M GOING
TO RENO TO LOOK FOR DAD.
- GOOD LUCK, FAVORITE SON.
narrator: SO ONCE AGAIN, MICHAEL
WENT AFTER THE FATHER...
WHO'D ONCE AGAIN ABANDONED HIM,
ONLY TO FIND...
HE WAS ABOUT TO DO
THE SAME THING TO HIS OWN SON.
- IT'S NOT HAPPENING, IS IT?
- SOMETHING CAME UP.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD
JUST TOLD HIS SON
THEY WOULDN'T
BE GOING TO THE CABIN.
- BUT THE CABIN'S IN LAKE TAHOE.
SO I'M SAYING THAT'S RIGHT NEAR
RENO, AND WE COULD--
- YEAH, BUT THIS IS GONNA
BE LIKE AN ADULT TRIP.
AUNT LINDSAY WILL BE HERE.
HI.
HEY, WHY DON'T YOU POP A TENT IN
FRONT WITH YOUR COUSIN MAEBY?
- WHAT?
NO!
- I'M NOT REALLY
THE OUTDOORSY TYPE.
- WELL, THEN THIS IS A GOOD
CHANCE FOR
YOU TO RUB OFF ON HER.
narrator: AS MICHAEL SET OUT
TO FIND HIS FATHER,
GOB THOUGHT HE WAS DOING
THE SAME.
- [sighs]
- THERE'S MY GUY!
[laughs]
HEY, BUDDY, COME ON.
- GETTIN' 'EM TO TRACK DOWN
YOUR DAD TOO?
- MY DAD ACTUALLY HAD THEM
TRACK ME DOWN.
- OH.
- BUT...IT DOES LOOK LIKE
HE'S NOT GONNA SHOW.
KIND OF FEEL LIKE THAT KID
WHO FOUND THE SEVERED HAND.
- [chuckles] HEY, DAD,
LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
- ANYTHING FOR
HIS FATHER'S APPROVAL.
HEARTBREAKING.
- YOU LOOK FAMILIAR.
- I THINK THAT'S BECAUSE
WE ACTUALLY KIND OF LOOK ALIKE.
narrator: REMEMBER WHEN I SAID
GOB HAD A SON?
- I'M GOB.
narrator:
I WASN'T JUST SAYING THAT.
IN HIGH SCHOOL, GOB BECAME
INTIMATE WITH THESE GIRLS.
THESE GIRLS GOT PREGNANT.
THIS ONE HAD A BABY.
AND THAT BABY WOULD
GROW UP TO BE--
- STEVE HOLT.
ALL I EVER WANTED WAS TO SPEND A
LITTLE TIME WITH MY DAD.
MAYBE GO CAMPING. BUT I GUESS
THAT WILL NEVER HAPPEN.
- LOOK, I KNOW THIS IS GONNA
SOUND KIND OF CRAZY,
BUT MY FAMILY HAS A CABIN IN THE
WOODS FOR ONE MORE NIGHT.
MAYBE WE COULD GO UP TO RENO,
GET THE KEYS AND GO CAMPING.
YOU KNOW, SORT OF...
A SON-AND-SON THING.
narrator:
IF STEVE HAD HAD A FATHER,
HE WOULD'VE WARNED HIM...
NOT TO GO INTO THE WOODS
WITH STRANGE MEN,
BUT HE DIDN'T.
- SURE! LET'S GO!
- OKAY. GREAT.
THIS IS ME RIGHT HERE.
- OKAY.
YEAH, BABY!
- STEVE HOLT!
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
ARRIVED IN RENO,
A CITY COMPETING WITH
LAS VEGAS' SUCCESSFUL...
"WHAT HAPPENS IN VEGAS
STAYS IN VEGAS" CAMPAIGN,
AND SET ABOUT SEARCHING
FOR BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
- I'M LOOKING FOR A MAN
WHO'S PROBABLY IN THE SEEDY
UNDERBELLY OF RENO.
- OH, THE CHRISTIAN LEAGUE
HAD THE SEEDY UNDERBELLY
SHUT DOWN.
NOW IT'S A SWALLOWS.
narrator: SWALLOWS WAS A
FAMILY-STYLE RESTAURANT BY DAY,
AND AN ANYTHING-GOES,
PANSEXUAL BAZAAR BY NIGHT.
- CAN I INTEREST YOU IN A
SMOOTHIE OR AN AMYL--MICHAEL!
- TOBIAS, I THOUGHT THAT
YOU WERE IN VEGAS WITH KITTY
IN THE BLUE MAN GROUP?
- NO, AS IT TURNS OUT,
THE PART THAT I'D...
DESTROYED MY LIFE TO GET
HAD ALREADY BEEN CAST.
narrator: THE ROLE WAS FILLED
BY GEORGE SR.,
WHO USED IT
TO HIDE IN PLAIN SIGHT.
THAT IS, UNTIL HE CHOKED
ON A MARSHMALLOW...
AND ALMOST DIED WHEN
NO ONE NOTICED HE TURNED BLUE.
- SO, KITTY SUGGESTED WE COME UP
HERE TO TRY OUT IN RENO, AND--
- UH, I'LL BE HONEST,
MICHAEL--
LEAVING LINDSAY WAS THE BIGGEST
LITTLE MISTAKE I'VE EVER MADE.
I CAN'T SEEM TO CALL HER THOUGH.
DAMN THIS PRIDE OF MINE!
- TUNA MELT'S UP,
AND YOU NEED TO FLIP THE
CUSHIONS IN THE GRIND ROOM.
- YES, SIR. RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
OH, GREAT.
NOW I'M GONNA BE SMELLING
TO HIGH HEAVEN LIKE A TUNA MELT.
- TOBIAS WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
IF I TOLD YOU
THAT LINDSAY MIGHT BE WILLING
TO GET BACK TOGETHER WITH YOU?
- OH, UH,
I'LL CALL HER RIGHT NOW.
- ACTUALLY, WHY DON'T YOU LET ME
HANDLE IT? YOU KNOW LINDSAY.
SHE ONLY
WANTS WHAT SHE CAN'T HAVE.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO
ABOUT KITTY?
- I CAN'T LIE TO YOU, MICHAEL.
KITTY LEFT ME TWO DAYS AGO.
THERE'S A BLUE HANDPRINT ON
THE BACK OF YOUR HEAD, KITTY.
ARE YOU SEEING SOMEONE ELSE?
- FACE IT, TOBIAS.
IT'S OVER!
- SAY GOOD-BYE TO THESE!
- THOSE ARE BLUE TOO!
- THERE WERE
BLUE HANDPRINTS ON THEM?
- YES. AND I SWEAR TO YOU,
THEY WEREN'T--
- YOURS. NO, I KNOW.
IT ALL POINTS TO DAD.
DAD'S IN RENO,
KITTY'S IN RENO.
DAD'S IN KITTY,
AND HE MUST BE A BLUE MAN.
I'M GONNA GO CHECK OUT
THE THEATER.
- OKAY, I'LL MEET YOU THERE.
I JUST HAVE TO BREAK DOWN
THE SALAD BAR AND
SET UP THE LEATHER PONY.
- WHAT'S A LEATHER PONY?
- I DON'T KNOW.
WE DON'T HAVE THAT AT LUNCH.
narrator:
SO MICHAEL CALLED LINDSAY
TO SAY HE'D FOUND HER HUSBAND.
- ALL RIGHT, I'M ON MY WAY.
- NO, NO. I'LL JUST BRING
HIM BACK WITH ME.
- HE WANTS TO COME HOME?
- I MEAN, AGAINST HIS WILL.
- WELL, KNOCK HIM OUT IF YOU
HAVE TO. HE'S MY HUSBAND!
- JUST WATCH THE KIDS
LIKE YOU PROMISED, OKAY?
- I'M NOT--
- NEITHER AM I!
- HOLD IT.
narrator: AND THE KIDS FOUND
THEMSELVES CLOSER THAN EVER
ON THE BUMPY ROAD TO RENO.
[cell phone ringing]
- HELLO?
- LINDSAY, HEY, HI.
MICHAEL SAID NOT TO CALL YOU,
BUT I MISS YOU SO MUCH.
- YOU MISS ME?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- NOTHING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I WAS DRIVING OUT THERE,
BUT THIS IS CRAZY.
WE HAVE TO BE REALISTIC.
- BUT, NO, NO, THE THING IS,
I CAN'T LEAVE KITTY.
WHAT, WITH ALL THE SEXUAL
INTERCOURSE AND WHATNOT.
- YOU BASTARD!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- NOTHING!
- I WILL BE BACKSTAGE...
AFTER THE BLUE MAN SHOW
WHETHER KITTY LIKES IT OR NOT.
- SOUNDS GOOD.
ONE QUICK QUESTION.
WHAT IF KITTY'S NOT THERE
AND I'M LESS OF A BLUE MAN
AND MORE OF A COCKTAIL WAITRESS?
- SHE'S TURNING AGAIN.
- HANG UP!
- I'LL SEE YOU THERE.
THANK YOU. BYE.
narrator: MICHAEL WAS ALREADY AT
THE THEATER
LOOKING FOR GEORGE SR,
WHEN HE RAN INTO BARRY
DOING THE SAME THING.
- HEY! BARRY.
- HI, MIKEY.
SO, HOW MUCH DO YOU KNOW?
- I KNOW THAT OSCAR IS IN
PRISON,
AND THAT MY FATHER
IS A BLUE MAN,
AND THAT YOU ARE CLEARLY
IN CAHOOTS WITH HIM.
- OOH, A LOT.
- WHERE IS HE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I WAS GONNA MEET HIM HERE, BUT
HE MUST'VE SEEN YOU AND RUN OFF.
I WAS GONNA GIVE HIM THIS--
$250,000 AND A PASSPORT.
- JUST A PASSPORT.
- WELL, I WAS UP FOR SO LONG.
- BARRY, YOU'RE FIRED.
- WHAT?
- YEAH.
- JUST LIKE THAT?
NO WARNING?
YOU'RE MY ONLY CLIENT.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO NOW,
TURN TRICKS ON THE STREET?
HOW MUCH YOU THINK I CAN GET
FOR THAT BY THE WAY?
- THIS IS CRAZY.
I'VE GOT TO LET
OSCAR OUT OF PRISON.
- WHAT ABOUT MAKING OUT?
FIFTY DOLLARS, OR IS THAT JUST
L.A.? AM I JUST--
narrator: SOON, LINDSAY ARRIVED
AT THE HOTEL,
AND THE KIDS
FINALLY FACED FACTS.
- LOOK, IT WAS JUST A HALF KISS.
MAYBE THAT'S THE REASON
WHY WE'RE ACTING WEIRD.
- IT WAS BECAUSE WE DIDN'T
FINISH THE KISS? IS THAT WHAT--
- YEAH. DO YOU THINK WE SHOULD
JUST FINISH THE KISS?
GET IT OUT OF THE WAY.
- LET'S GET IT OUT OF THE WAY.
- HEY, KIDS, BRING THE BAGS.
WE'RE SHARING A ROOM.
- ALRIGHT, LET'S MEET BACK HERE
TOMORROW MORNING, OKAY?
- YEAH.
- GO.
- ARE YOU--
YEAH, I'M GONNA--
I'M GONNA STAY OUT HERE AND
WATCH THAT FAMOUS RENO SUNSET.
- ISN'T IT BEHIND YOU?
- THERE'S--
YEAH, BUT THERE'S MIRRORS.
IT'LL ACTUALLY LOOK CLOSER.
narrator: WHILE GEORGE MICHAEL
WAITED FOR THE SUNSET,
ANOTHER SET OF SONS ARRIVED.
- MICHAEL SAID HE'D MEET
ME HERE.
I'LL GET THE KEYS
TO THE CABIN, SON.
- I'LL GO BUY SOME
FISHING STUFF, SON.
- SO, WHERE DID YOU
GET THIS KID?
- YEAH,
I GUESS I CAN TELL YOU NOW.
WE WERE BOTH WAITING FOR
OUR DADS AT THAT GARDEN
WHERE THE LITTLE BOY
FOUND THE ARM.
KID'S AMAZING, THOUGH.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE...
I WISH HE COULD BE MY DAD.
- OKAY, UM, YOUR DAD'S NOT
TRYING TO FIND YOU, YOUR SON IS.
THAT KID'S YOUR SON.
YOU'RE THE DAD, HMM?
- I'VE MADE A HUGE
TINY MISTAKE.
- GOB.
YOU CAN'T JUST LEAVE YOUR SON
IN THE MIDDLE
OF A PARKING LOT IN RENO.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN MICHAEL SAW HIS OWN SON
IN A PARKING LOT IN RENO.
- HE DROVE ALL THE WAY UP HERE
TO BE WITH ME. WOW.
WELL, I GUESS I'M, UH--
I'M NO BETTER THAN--
NO, I'M BETTER.
narrator:
THEY WERE AN HOUR OUT OF RENO
WHEN GEORGE MICHAEL WOKE UP.
- YOU WERE OUT LIKE A LIGHT,
PAL.
OUR DREAMS ARE ABOUT
TO COME TRUE.
- MAEBY?
- DEFINITELY!
WE ARE GOING CAMPING.
IT'S FINALLY HAPPENING.
- IT'S NEVER HAPPENING.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST
SURPRISED HIS SLEEPING SON
BY TAKING HIM CAMPING.
- I PUT THIS OFF TOO LONG,
AND IT'S TOO IMPORTANT.
YOUR UNCLE OSCAR CAN STAY IN
PRISON ONE MORE DAY, RIGHT?
narrator: NOT ACCORDING TO THAT
DAY'S BLOG ON IMOSCAR.COM.
- THIS HERE IS WAY MORE
IMPORTANT
THAN ME TRYING TO FIND MY
FATHER.
ALTHOUGH, I WAS VERY CLOSE.
I ALMOST HAD POP-POP IN RENO.
- ME TOO.
narrator:
AS MICHAEL WAS FORCIBLY TAKING
HIS SON OUT TO THE CABIN,
LUCILLE WAS READY TO FORCIBLY
THROW HERS OUT.
[loud snoring]
[snoring]
- WELL, THAT WAS A FREEBIE.
narrator: LUCILLE DIDN'T
TRUST HERSELF
TO BE IN THE HOUSE
WHEN BUSTER RETURNED.
SO, SHE HEADED OFF
TO THE CABIN
MICHAEL SAID
WOULD BE UNOCCUPIED.
TOBIAS, MEANWHILE,
WAS LOOKING FOR A WAY
TO MAKE HIS WIFE JEALOUS...
BY CONVINCING HER THAT
HE WAS NOT ONLY A BLUE MAN,
BUT STILL WITH KITTY,
WHEN HE CAME ACROSS A MAKEUP
WOMAN WHO, COINCIDENTALLY,
LOOKED A GREAT DEAL LIKE KITTY.
- IF THIS TABLEAU I RE-CREATE,
PERHAPS I CAN RE-SNARE MY MATE.
narrator: GEE, WHY WOULDN'T
SHE WANT HIM BACK?
AND MICHAEL AND HIS SON ARRIVED
AT THE CABIN IN THE WOODS.
- LOOKS LIKE THEY HAVE
TRUCKED OFF THE BEDROOMS.
MAYBE WE'LL JUST SET UP
SOME SLEEPING BAGS
RIGHT HERE
IN THE LIVING ROOM, HUH?
narrator: LUCILLE, MEANWHILE,
HEARD A FAMILIAR SOUND.
[snoring]
- OH, COME ON!
- MOTHER?
- WHAT THE HELL ARE
YOU DOING BACK THERE?
- I DECIDED TO SLEEP IN THE CAR
SO MY SNORING WOULDN'T
BOTHER YOU,
AND I LEFT THAT RECORDING
OF MY SNORING
SO YOU WOULDN'T
KNOW I'M GONE.
- WE'RE HALFWAY TO THE CABIN.
I'M GONNA DROP YOU
BY THIS LIGHT.
- OR I COULD COME WITH YOU.
THAT MIGHT BE THE EXACT SHOT IN
THE ARM OUR RELATIONSHIP NEEDS.
- WELL, AT LEAST I'LL
HAVE SOMEONE
TO TALK TO ON THE WAY UP.
[snoring]
- THIS IS FUN, ISN'T IT?
THIS IS JUST LIKE WHEN WE USED
TO LIVE UP IN THE ATTIC.
- YEAH.
OR--OR WE COULD
GO BACK TO RENO.
- GO BACK TO RENO?
YOU DON'T WANNA BE HERE?
YOU'VE BEEN SLEEPING IN
THE STAIR CAR
JUST SO WE CAN
SPEND TIME TOGETHER.
- THAT'S NOT TOTALLY TRUE
THOUGH.
I'M JUST IN THE MIDDLE
OF A PROBLEM RIGHT NOW.
- OH, YEAH?
WELL, LET'S TALK ABOUT IT.
- I CAN'T TALK ABOUT IT
WITH YOU.
- WHY NOT?
- IT'S ABOUT A GIRL, AND
YOU'RE NOT GONNA LIKE THIS.
- IS IT ABOUT ANN?
- NO.
- OH.
OF COURSE I DON'T LIKE IT.
I LIKE ANN.
- NO, IT'S JUST--
IT'S A PROBLEM
WITHOUT AN ANSWER.
- WELL, EVERY PROBLEM
HAS AN ANSWER.
YOU'RE PROBABLY JUST CONFUSED
BECAUSE YOU'RE GOING THROUGH
ALL OF THIS ALONE.
AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHY WE NEED
TO SPEND THIS TIME TOGETHER.
- YEAH, I GUESS SO.
- I KNOW SO.
SO HERE'S THE PLAN.
TOMORROW MORNING
WE'RE GONNA GET UP EARLY.
BEFORE WE TELL THE COPS THAT
POP-POP ESCAPED FROM PRISON,
WE'RE GONNA GO DOWN TO THE LAKE,
DISCUSS YOUR GIRL PROBLEM,
AND IT'S GONNA BE FUN.
ESPECIALLY THE PART
ABOUT THE COPS.
ALL RIGHT?
WHATEVER YOUR PROBLEM
IS WITH THE GIRL,
WE'RE GONNA FIGURE IT OUT.
THAT'S WHAT
THIS PLACE IS FOR.
THAT, AND CHEATING ON GANGY.
- YOU KNOW, I'M REALLY GLAD YOU
BROUGHT ME HERE, DAD.
- YEAH, WE NEEDED THIS.
AND THIS TIME, I'M NOT GONNA
LET THE FAMILY DRAG ME AWAY.
narrator: THE NEXT MORNING,
MICHAEL ROSE EARLY TO SPEND
THE DAY WITH HIS SON,
ONLY TO FIND HIMSELF,
ONCE AGAIN,
DRAGGED AWAY BY HIS FAMILY.
- DAD! WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
- SORRY.
I CAN'T LET YOU LET OSCAR OUT OF
PRISON OR THEY'LL COME FOR ME.
HEY, HOW DO YOU LIKE
THE CABIN?
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
LUCILLE ARRIVES AT THE CABIN.
- [bleep] ME.
THERE'S NO CABIN.
- MOTHER?
- OH, MY GOD!
YOU STILL DOING
BREAKFAST BURRITOS?
[loud splash]
narrator: MAEBY FINDS SOMEONE TO
HELP HER FORGET HER COUSIN.
- BEING STOOD UP.
- YEAH, ME TOO.
narrator: HER COUSIN.
- WANNA MAKE OUT?
- YEAH, SURE. WHY NOT?
narrator: AND LINDSAY CATCHES UP
WITH TOBIAS.
- GET YOUR HANDS OFF
MY HUSBAND, KITTY.
- DID SOMEONE SAY "HUSBAND"?
- I WANT A DIVORCE.
- AND I WOULD BE THRILLED TO
REPRESENT EITHER ONE OF YOU.
THAT'LL BE $50.