narrator: PREVIOUSLY ON
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL AND HIS SON WERE CAMPING
OUT AT THE FAMILY CABIN...
BEFORE IT WAS TO BE RELOCATED.
- I'M JUST IN THE MIDDLE OF A
STUPID GIRL PROBLEM THAT'S ALL.
- I DON'T EVEN HAVE A GIRL,
MUCH LESS A STUPID ONE.
- NO, THE PROBLEM IS STUPID.
THE GIRL ISN'T STUPID.
narrator: BUT IF THEY EVER HAD A
CHILD, IT WOULD BE--
BECAUSE THE GIRL
WAS HIS COUSIN MAEBY.
- TOMORROW MORNING,
BEFORE WE TELL THE COPS
THAT THAT'S NOT
POP-POP IN PRISON,
WE'RE GONNA GO DOWN TO THE LAKE,
WE'RE GONNA DISCUSS
YOUR GIRL PROBLEM MAN-TO-MAN,
AND IT'S GONNA BE FUN.
ESPECIALLY THE PART
ABOUT THE COPS.
narrator:
BUT POP-POP HAD OTHER PLANS,
AND MICHAEL AWOKE TO FIND
HIS CAMPING TRIP GOING SOUTH.
- WELL, YOU BETTER GET UP NOW
IF YOU WANT TO SEE THE LAKE.
narrator: AND THAT WAS WHEN
GEORGE SR. MADE A DESPERATE
PLEA.
- PROMISE ME YOU WON'T
SEND ME BACK TO PRISON--
SO I CAN BE WITH
MY DEAR LOVE LUCILLE...
IN THE TWILIGHT
OF HER FACE.
narrator: MICHAEL DIDN'T SEND
HIS FATHER BACK TO PRISON,
BUT INSTEAD ARRANGED FOR HIM TO
BE PLACED UNDER HOUSE ARREST.
- GEORGE, WE'RE NEVER
GOING TO BE
OUT OF EACH OTHER'S SIGHT.
narrator: WHICH MADE THIS WOMAN
HIS WARDEN.
- OH, DEAR GOD.
SEND ME BACK TO PRISON.
YOU GOTTA SEND ME
BACK TO PRISON.
- MORE TOUCHING.
narrator: MICHAEL WENT TO HIS
PARENTS' PENTHOUSE TO DISCUSS...
HIS FATHER'S EVER-WORSENING
LEGAL SITUATION.
- WHERE IS EVERYBODY?
- HOW SHOULD I KNOW, MICHAEL?
AS SOON AS FATHER CAME BACK,
I'VE BEEN LIKE
THE INVISIBLE MAN.
"HELLO! CAN ANYONE SEE ME?"
- WHERE'S YOUR HAND, ANYWAY?
- WHY EVEN BOTHER
GETTING DRESSED UP?
I HAVE NO ONE.
- BUSTER, COME ON NOW.
IF YOU'RE REALLY LONELY, MAYBE
IT'S TIME YOU WENT OUT THERE...
AND YOU GOT YOURSELF A GIRL--
A PET.
- HOW ABOUT A TURTLE?
- GREAT.
- I'VE ALWAYS LOVED THOSE
LEATHERY LITTLE SNAPPY FACES.
[giggles]
- YOU CERTAINLY HAVE A TYPE.
- MOTHER, HAVE YOU SEEN
MY RUBBER HAND?
- OH, IT'S IN THE DISHWASHER.
YOUR FATHER AND I WERE USING IT
FOR SOMETHING.
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
CAN'T YOU KEEP MY HAND
TO YOURSELF?
- UH, "USED IT FOR SOMETHING"?
- HE'S JUST JEALOUS THAT I HAVE
A MAN BACK IN MY LIFE.
AND GUESS WHAT ELSE
IS BACK.
- MY BREAKFAST?
- MY FRISKINESS.
[whispering]
MAMA HORNY, MICHAEL.
- NO, IT'S MY BREAKFAST.
I'M AMAZED DAD HASN'T STRANGLED
HIMSELF WITH HIS BELT YET.
- OH, WE'RE INTO ALL KINDS
OF FREAKY STUFF.
- WHY DO I EAT BREAKFAST
BEFORE I COME HERE?
[clattering]
- WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
- WELL, NOW THAT DAD'S BACK,
I'M GOING TO PERFORM...
ONE GRAND ILLUSION FOR HIM
BEFORE HE STRANGLES HIMSELF
WITH HIS BELT.
- NO, NO. TURNS OUT
THEY'RE INTO THAT.
- OH.
WELL, CHECK IT.
THE ILLUSION IS CALLED
"FREE BIRD."
A MAGICAL BIRD--
ME IN A BEAK--
STANDS ON A PLATFORM.
THERE'S A PUFF OF SMOKE,
THEN I'M GONE.
THEN SECONDS LATER, HIGH ABOVE
IN A ONCE-EMPTY CAGE--
WHO SHOULD APPEAR?
- A GUY THAT KIND OF LOOKS
LIKE YOU?
- NO. THAT'S NOT
HOW I DO THE TRICK.
EVEN IF IT WAS, HOW'D THE
LOOK-ALIKE GET UP THERE?
- HE WAS HIDING BEHIND
THIS MIRROR HERE?
- NO!
FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
DAD ASKED ME TO DO THIS...
ON THE DAY HE PLEADS
NOT GUILTY...
AS A SPECTACULAR PROTEST.
A "PROTEST-ACULAR."
MAYBE EVEN GET IT
ON THE LOCAL NEWS.
- EXCUSE ME.
I WAS JUST LOOKING
FOR A MARKER--
A MAGIC MARKER.
- I WANT IT OUT OF MY LIVING
ROOM.
PUT IT IN BUSTER'S ROOM.
THAT'S WHERE SHE KEEPS THINGS
SHE HAS NO NEED FOR.
[sniffs]
OH, GOD.
I'M GONNA RUN THIS THROUGH AGAIN
ON "POTS AND PANS."
- YOU KNOW, GOB, INSTEAD OF
TRYING TO IMPRESS A FATHER
THAT COULDN'T CARE LESS
ABOUT YOU,
WHY DON'T YOU TRY SPENDING
SOME TIME WITH YOUR SON...
WHO'S DYING
TO RECONNECT WITH YOU?
narrator: GOB HAD DISCOVERED HE
WAS THE FATHER OF THIS BOY.
- WELL, THEN JUST TELL HIM THAT
STEVE HOLT STOPPED BY, OKAY?
- OKAY.
narrator: HE'D BEEN DUCKING HIM
EVER SINCE.
- TOM?
COME ON OVER HERE.
I'VE GOT A VITAMIN
FOR YOU.
HEY, HE'S THE ONE
WHO CAN'T SEE ME.
- BECAUSE YOU WERE HIDING
IN THE TRICK?
- ILLUSION, MICHAEL.
I SO VERY MUCH
WOULD LIKE TO BE...
IN YOUR "PROSTATE-ICULAR"--
AS YOUR LOOK-ALIKE.
- RIGHT.
THEY'RE GONNA SEE THE INK.
IT'S MORE OF A LEADING MAN ROLE.
BUT IT'S NOT REALLY
DONE THAT WAY.
- GUESS I SHOULDN'T HAVE
USED A PERMANENT MARKER.
- STARTING TO SEE WHY
YOU WANT THAT DIVORCE.
- YEAH, WELL, ACTUALLY,
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
INSTEAD OF SPENDING MONEY
ON A DIVORCE--
WHICH CAN BE SLOW-- WELL, MAYBE
I SHOULD GET SOMETHING FASTER.
- NOT THE CAR.
I SAID NO TO THE VOLVO.
- THE LEXUS.
THE VOLVO DIDN'T HAVE SATELLITE
RADIO, WHICH IS CRAZY.
I MEAN,
WHAT ARE WE, AMISH?
- I KNEW YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE THE GUTS
TO GO THROUGH WITH THE DIVORCE.
- YOU'RE ONE TO TALK.
YOU HAVEN'T HAD A SERIOUS
RELATIONSHIP SINCE YOUR WIFE.
AND...YOU GUYS WEREN'T EVEN
SPEAKING TOWARD THE END.
- LOT OF THAT WAS THE COMA.
- YEAH.
I'VE HEARD YOUR SIDE OF IT.
[door buzzer]
YOU HAVEN'T HAD THE GUTS
TO MEET SOMEONE ELSE.
- UH--
- LOOK WHO FINALLY GOT
HIS PANTS ON.
YOU'VE GOT 10 MINUTES.
- YOU GOTTA GET ME OUT OF HERE.
- YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT SAID NO TO PRISON.
- I WAS WRONG.
THERE YOU JUST HAD
TO SHUT YOUR EYES AND TAKE IT.
HERE YOU HAVE TO SHUT YOUR EYES
AND GIVE IT.
NOW LISTEN.
WE CAN'T JUST GO IN THERE
AND PLEAD NOT GUILTY.
WE HAVE TO HAVE SOMEONE BIG
BEHIND US.
OUR OWN PRIVATE MATLOCK.
SO I MADE SOME CALLS,
AND I GOT HIM.
- GOT WHO?
- ANDY GRIFFITH.
WHAT, YOU NEVER SAW MATLOCK?
- NOT A REAL ATTORNEY, DAD.
- NOW, FOR 10 GRAND,
HE'LL ACTUALLY...
SIT BEHIND US IN COURT
AND READ THE PAPER.
FOR 15, HE'LL ACTUALLY SIT
AT THE DEFENSE TABLE.
FOR $20,000, HE'LL TWICE--
[whispering] LEAN FORWARD AND
WHISPER SOMETHING IN YOUR EAR.
OH. WHITE SUIT--
THAT'S EXTRA.
- WELL, THAT'S AN AWFUL LOT
OF MONEY
FOR THE STUPIDEST
IDEA I'VE EVER HEARD.
- THE JURIES LOVE HIM.
- THAT'S JUST IT, DAD.
THERE WON'T BE A JURY
BECAUSE WE ARE PLEADING GUILTY.
- I AM NOT GUILT--
I DIDN'T WANT TO TELL YOU THIS.
ARE READY FOR THE BOMBSHELL?
- ANDY GRIFFITH WASN'T
THE BOMBSHELL?
- I'M A PATSY.
I WAS SET UP...BY THE BRITS.
A GROUP OF BRITISH BUILDERS
OPERATING OUTSIDE THE O.C.--
- DON'T CALL IT THAT.
- CONTACTED ME...
FOR A PARTNERSHIP
TO BUILD HOMES OVERSEAS.
I DID NOT KNOW THEY MEANT IRAQ.
- WE'VE GOT A PICTURE OF YOU
WITH SADDAM HUSSEIN.
- I-I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE GUY
WHO PLAYED THE SOUP NAZI.
- COME ON.
- I TOLD HIM HOW MUCH
I LIKED HIS WORK.
THE BRITS USED THAT PICTURE
TO BLACKMAIL ME.
A PICTURE LIKE THAT, MICHAEL,
CAN END YOUR CAREER.
- NOT IN EVERY CASE.
- THESE ARE DANGEROUS PEOPLE,
MICHAEL.
THEY'LL DO WHATEVER IT TAKES...
TO GET INSIDE THIS FAMILY
AND JUST BRING US DOWN.
- BRITISH PEOPLE.
- OH, THEY'RE POLITE
AND THE MEN ALL SOUND GAY,
BUT THEY WILL RIP OUT
YOUR HEART AND--
THEIR BREATH--
- AND YOU WANT TO GO
AFTER THESE PEOPLE?
- WELL, YES, IT TAKES
A LITTLE COURAGE, MICHAEL.
I KNOW THAT'S NOT
YOUR STRONGEST SUIT.
YOU'RE--YOU'RE EVEN SCARED TO
ASK A GIRL OUT ON A DATE.
- WH-- WHY DOES EVERYBODY THINK
THAT I'M SCARED OF GIRLS?
- BECAUSE YOU'RE A CHICKEN.
YOU'RE A CHICKEN.
- NO, I'M NOT.
- [imitates chicken]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- MICHAEL AND WOMEN?
[imitates chicken]
- THAT'S WHAT I WAS JUST
TELLING HIM.
[imitating chickens]
- LOOK, I HAVEN'T FOUND
THE RIGHT GIRL.
WHEN I DO,
I WILL ASK HER OUT.
HAS ANYONE IN THIS FAMILY
EVER EVEN SEEN A CHICKEN?
- WAIT, WAIT.
I'VE GOT THE PERFECT THING.
- THAT'S ENOUGH.
I WILL GIVE IT ONE DAY.
ALL RIGHT?
I'LL SEE IF THERE'S ANY EVIDENCE
OF THESE NEFARIOUS BRITS.
BUT I'M WARNING YOU-- IF I
CAN'T, WE'RE PLEADING GUILTY.
YOU'RE EITHER GOING TO JAIL,
OF IF THE JUDGE SHOWS
ABSOLUTELY NO MERCY AT ALL,
YOU'LL BE STAYING HERE
WITH MY MOTHER.
LINDSAY, I DIDN'T WANT
TO TELL YOU EARLIER,
BUT I DID GET YOU A CAR.
- IS IT THE LEXUS?
- IT'S MORE LIKE A LINCOLN.
[imitating chicken]
OH, COME ON!
- THERE'S NO SATELLITE RADIO,
BUT THERE'S A BANJO
IN THE CLOSET.
AND WATCH OUT
FOR LIVE-INS.
YOU WILL GET SOME LIVE-INS.
narrator: MICHAEL WAS
INVESTIGATING
HIS FATHER'S CASE...
IN THE ENGLISH SECTION
OF ORANGE COUNTY.
- LANES REVERSE!
[tires squealing]
YOU'RE DRIVING ON THE WRONG
SIDE, YOU BLOOMIN' IDIOT!
- I NEED TO CHECK
THE RECORDS...
FOR ANY BRITISH-OWNED
BUILDING BUSINESSES...
THAT WOULD HAVE APPLIED FOR
LICENSE ABOUT 10 YEARS AGO.
- OH, I'M SO SORRY.
YOU NEED A U.K. PASSPORT
TO CHECK THOSE FILES.
THEY'RE FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY.
- [singing]
FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY
- DON'T I LOOK KIND OF BRITISH?
- PERHAPS IF YOU'RE WILLING
TO LOSE 20 POUNDS.
narrator: THE CLERK WAS ASKING
FOR A BRIBE,
BUT THIS WAS LOST
ON MICHAEL.
- YOU GUYS DO GO FOR THE
JUGULAR.
- IF YOU FIND SOMEONE WITH A
PASSPORT, WE'RE HERE TILL 8:00--
AND DO STAY FOR THE POPPINS.
narrator: SO MICHAEL WENT
TO THE LOCAL PUB--
- BLOODY YANK!
narrator: TO SEE IF HE COULD
FIND SOMEONE...
WITH A BRITISH PASSPORT.
- WELCOME TO THE YELLOW FANG.
I AM LIONEL, AND THE SOUP
OF THE DAY IS--
WHAT'S THE SOUP
OF THE DAY, MUM?
- BREAD.
- AND THE SOUP OF THE DAY
IS BREAD--
UNLESS YOU'RE JUST HERE
FOR THE POPPINS.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN MICHAEL SAW THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL WOMAN HE'D EVER SEEN.
NOT HER.
WAIT FOR IT.
- A-ARE YOU FROM WEE BRITAIN?
- GREAT BRITAIN, ACTUALLY.
- I-I WAS WONDERING IF YOU MIGHT
BE WILLING
TO GO SOMEWHERE WITH ME.
I-I WILL PAY YOU.
- YOU'LL PAY ME?
- NOT--NOT FOR SEX.
YOU'RE GONNA THINK
THAT I'M JACK THE RIPPER, RIGHT?
DIDN'T HE KILL
PROSTITUTES OR--
- I'M NOT A PROSTITUTE.
THEN I SHALL LET YOU LIVE.
[chuckles]
THIS IS MY WORST HELLO.
LET ME TRY AGAIN.
MY NAME IS MICHAEL.
- RITA.
- SO I NEED ACCESS
TO THESE FILES...
THAT ARE APPARENTLY
FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY.
- WELL, LUCKY FOR YOU,
MY WHOLE FACE IS BRITISH.
- [singing]
FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY
- IT'S JUST ACROSS THE STREET.
I REALLY APPRECIATE--
HELLO.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU WERE OPEN TILL 8:00.
- OH, YES-- G.M.T.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS ON GREENWICH MEAN TIME.
- WHAT A CURIOUS STREET.
UH-- WAIT, WAIT, RITA.
I DON'T SUPPOSE THAT YOU'RE
HERE TOMORROW MORNING?
- OH, NO.
NOT IN THE MORNING, NO.
I'LL BE BACK AT SLOWBROOKE.
- SLOWBROOKE--THE PRIVATE
SCHOOL.
YOU TEACH KIDS, HUH?
- I LIKE TO THINK
THEY TEACH ME.
- LIKE WHAT? HOW TO
EAT CRAYONS, THROW TANTRUMS--
- OH, NO.
NOT WHEN I'M THERE.
I'M VERY GOOD.
- I-I DIDN'T MEAN TO IMPUGN
YOUR ABILITY OR, UH--
IT'S TURNING INTO
ONE OF MY WORST GOOD-BYES.
FAREWELL, AND, UH,
OUR PATHS SHAN'T CROSS AGAIN.
[chuckles]
AS YOU LIKE IT.
narrator: MICHAEL WOULD HAVE
WALKED AWAY FOREVER,
BUT HE WAS STRUCK BY
SOMETHING HE REMEMBERED
FROM HIS CHILDHOOD.
- YOU KNOW--
[groans]
announcer: LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IT'S THE FLIGHT OF
THE MARY POPPINS.
MARY POPPINS WILL TAKE--
- WELL, MUST BE THE POPPINS.
- OH, I'M SORRY.
IT'S WRONG TO LAUGH.
- NO, NO, IT WAS GOOD.
I LIKED IT.
I WAS JUST GONNA ASK YOU--
PRE-SCHOOLS JUST GO
HALF DAY, RIGHT?
I'M NOT TRYING TO PICK YOU UP,
BUT IS THERE ANY WAY
THAT I CAN COME BY,
PICK YOU UP,
BRING YOU HERE?
- YEAH, I-- I, UH--
I SUPPOSE I COULD SNEAK OUT
AT NAP TIME.
- YES? PERFECT. GREAT.
- MMM.
- AND I SHALL DROP YOU OFF
ALIVE, HOOKER OR NO.
[no audible dialogue]
narrator: TOBIAS, STILL HOPING
TO BE IN GOB'S TRICK,
VENTURED INTO A COSTUME SHOP
HE'D STUMBLED UPON--
- OH, LOOK WHO'S BACK.
narrator: YEARS EARLIER.
- ARE YOU GONNA BUY THIS TIME,
OR YOU JUST CURIOUS?
- I SUPPOSE
I'M, UH, BUY-CURIOUS.
I HAVE A BIG TV OPPORTUNITY.
- THIS IS WHERE ALL THE BIG TVs
COME.
- [chuckles]
- UH, LET'S START WITH
THE EVE ARDEN.
- ALL RIGHT.
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
CALLED HIS SISTER.
- I WANTED TO TELL YOU
THAT I GOT MYSELF A DATE
WITH A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN...
NAMED RITA,
AND YOU'RE THE CHICKEN, NOT ME.
CLUCK, CLUCK, CLUCK,
CLUCK, CLUCK--
[horn honking]
- [screams]
- OKAY. THAT'S A PRETTY
GOOD CHICKEN.
[beeping]
- [horn honking]
- WATCH OUT!
[tires squealing]
- CRAZY BRIT!
- WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
- I KNOW WHAT YOU WERE
DOING BACK THERE.
AND IF YOU'VE GOT HALF
A-- [bleep] BRAIN,
YOU'LL LEAVE IT ALONE.
- YOU TALKING ABOUT
BACK IN WEE BRITAIN?
I WAS JUST ASKING
A FEW QUESTIONS.
- YEAH--
A FEW TOO MANY,
IF YOU ASK ME.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE SOMEONE
GOING AFTER SOME STUPID
PERSON IN YOUR FAMILY?
NOW, BACK OFF,
YOU-- [bleep] PONCE.
- WOW.
DAD WAS NOT KIDDING
ABOUT THEIR BREATH.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST
BEEN THREATENED...
BY A FOUL-MOUTHED
BRITISH MAN.
- IT'S MICHAEL.
I'M NOT DRESSED.
- GOB, THIS IS MICHAEL.
SHOULDN'T YOU BE GETTING READY
FOR YOUR "FREE BIRD" TRICK?
- I COULDN'T GET THE RIGHTS
TO "FREE BIRD."
- OH.
- I'M THINKING ABOUT
CALLING IT "FREE"--
I DON'T KNOW.
CHICKEN.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
INVESTIGATING DAD'S
SINISTER BRITISH CONNECTION.
- YEAH. I, UH, TRIED,
BUT, UH,
WHEN I WAS LEAVING,
ONE OF THOSE BRITISH GUYS
CAME AFTER ME AND TOLD ME
TO BACK OFF.
CAN'T BELIEVE IT, BUT DAD MAY
HAVE BEEN TELLING THE TRUTH.
THIS MIGHT BE DANGEROUS.
- SO YOU CAME BACK HERE
TO HIDE LIKE A CHILD.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
LOCKED IN MY OFFICE, EXACTLY?
- HIDING FROM A CHILD.
BIG DIFFERENCE.
- GOB, STEVE HOLT IS YOUR SON.
HE PROBABLY JUST FEELS
A CONNECTION.
- HE DOESN'T KNOW WHAT HE FEELS.
I'M TRIED OF BEING TOLD.
MY GOD.
WHAT IS THIS FEELING?
- YOU KNOW, THE FEELING
THAT YOU'RE--
THAT YOU'RE FEELING, IT'S JUST
WHAT MANY OF US CALL A FEELING.
- IT'S NOT LIKE ENVY--
OR EVEN HUNGRY.
- COULD IT BE LOVE?
- I KNOW WHAT AN ERECTION
FEELS LIKE, MICHAEL.
NO.
IT'S THE OPPOSITE.
IT'S LIKE MY HEART
IS GETTING HARD.
MAYBE I AM READY
TO BE A FATHER.
- HEY, DAD?
- WHOA!
- IT'S MY SON, GOB.
YOU KNOW, AND WHAT IS IT WITH
THE FATHERS IN THIS FAMILY
ALWAYS TRYING TO DECEIVE THEIR--
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL REALIZED THAT THE MAN...
WHO THREATENED HIM MUST HAVE
BEEN HIRED BY GEORGE SR.
- I'M THE PATSY.
WELL, I GOTTA GO.
GEORGE MICHAEL?
I'M SORRY, BUT WE'RE GONNA TALK
ABOUT THAT GIRL LATER, OKAY?
- NOW ALL I HAVE TO DO IS FIND
THAT LOOK-ALIKE, MICHAEL.
- MICHAEL?
HEY!
- THAT'S A WOMAN'S WIG.
- I WAS TOLD IT WAS A BOB.
- narrator: AND MICHAEL
CONFRONTED HIS FATHER.
- FIND OUT ANYTHING?
- YEAH, I DID, DAD.
I FOUND OUT NO MATTER HOW MANY
TIMES I PROMISE MYSELF...
THAT I'M NOT GONNA FALL FOR IT,
I ALWAYS END UP
GETTING HUSTLED BY YOU.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- THE GUY THAT YOU HIRED
TO THREATEN ME
AFTER I LOOKED
INTO THE BRITISH CONNECTION.
- WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
SOMEBODY THREATENED YOU?
- IT'S A WONDERFUL PERFORMANCE,
DAD.
YOU'RE A REGULAR BRAD GARRETT.
BUT I DON'T WATCH TV
AT 3:00 IN THE AFTERNOON,
AND YOU CAN FORGET
ABOUT PLEADING NOT GUILTY.
- GUILTY. WE GOTTA PLEAD GUILTY.
- WHAT?
- MICHAEL, I DIDN'T HIRE ANYONE,
I-I-I--I SWEAR.
IF SOMEONE CAME AFTER YOU,
THEY'RE FOR REAL.
- COME ON.
YOU SERIOUS?
- I TOLD YOU.
THESE ARE BAD GUYS.
THEY DO NOT WANT
THIS INFORMATION OUT.
- HE SAID HE WAS GONNA
COME AFTER SOMEBODY STUPID
IN OUR FAMILY.
THAT COULD BE BUSTER.
- [inhales sharply]
COULD BE GOB.
- YOU'RE NOT GUILTY.
- WE HAVE TO PLEAD GUILTY.
- WE GOTTA PLEAD GUILTY.
- WE GOTTA THROW OURSELVES
ON THE MERCY OF THE COURT.
- WE GOTTA GET ANDY GRIFFITH.
- IN THE SUIT.
narrator: AND MICHAEL WENT
TO CANCEL WITH RITA.
- SORRY. I JUST WANTED
TO LET YOU KNOW...
THAT I'M NOT GONNA BE NEEDING
YOUR PASSPORT AFTER ALL.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GO TO COURT,
PLEAD GUILTY.
THAT'LL BE THAT.
- SO IT'S BYE-BYE TO RITA, THEN?
- YES, I'LL SHAKE YOUR HAND
GOOD-BYE,
BUT, ACTUALLY, I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU MIGHT WANT TO--
- I WOULDN'T.
I'LL MAKE YOU BLUE.
narrator: RITA WAS JUST TALKING
ABOUT THE FINGER PAINT,
BUT MICHAEL DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
- I WAS JUST WONDERING...
IF YOU MIGHT WANT TO BID ME
FAIR MORROW.
narrator: MICHAEL WAS FILLED
WITH SELF-LOATHING.
HAD HE BEEN JACK THE RIPPER,
HE WOULD HAVE SOOTHED HIMSELF
IN A MOST UNSAVORY WAY.
BUT INSTEAD HE JUST
SAT IN HIS CAR...
AND ATE A WHOLE THING
OF CANDY BEANS.
AND BACK AT THE PENTHOUSE,
GOB HAD BEEN CALLED
TO SEE HIS FATHER.
- NEW PLAN, RIGHT?
YOU PUT ME IN THE TRICK.
YOU MAKE ME THE GUY
IN THE CAGE.
- OKAY, I JUST GOTTA SAY I'M
REALLY BLOWN AWAY BY THIS.
YOU REALLY WANT TO BE PART
OF MY WORLD.
- I DO.
- GOD, I FEEL LIKE MY HEART
IS STRAINING THROUGH MY SHIRT.
- THEY TAKE THE ANKLE MONITOR
OFF WHEN I GET TO COURT.
SO, YOU MAKE ME DISAPPEAR, YOU
PUT TOBIAS IN THE CAGE,
AND BY THE TIME THEY REALIZE
THAT THAT GUY IS NOT ME,
I'M RUNNING THROUGH THE STORM
DRAINS TO FREEDOM.
- WHERE EVERY DAY IT RAINS...
PENNIES FROM HEAVEN!
THIS...BIRD TODAY--
- GOB, I KNOW YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A TWIN FOR YOUR ILLUSION,
AND THERE'S SOMEBODY
I'D LIKE TO PUT IN A PLUG FOR.
UH-- CORRECTION.
MAKE THAT 4,000 PLUGS.
- OH, GOD!
- OH, COME ON.
- MR. GAY, HE'S BLEEDING.
MR. GAY--
- NO, NO, NO, NO--
I WAS SCARED TOO,
BUT I REALIZED IT WAS
OF BEING A LEADING MAN.
OH, I CAN JUST TASTE
THOSE MEATY LEADING-MAN PARTS
IN MY MOUTH.
- ALL RIGHT, LISTEN TO ME.
THE TRICK HAS CHANGED.
WE WANT YOU TO PLAY ME NOW.
- OH, BUT THAT WOULD MEAN
I'D HAVE TO SH--
SHAVE MY VERY...
TENDER HEAD. I SEE.
OKAY. WELL, PERHAPS
I JUMPED THE GUN...
ON THOSE NEW HEAD SHOTS.
narrator: AND LATER THAT DAY,
MICHAEL ARRIVED AT THE
COURTHOUSE.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE JUST
GIVING UP LIKE THIS.
- WELL, THE GUY THREATENED OUR
FAMILY.
WE HAVE TO PLEAD GUILTY.
- NO, I'M TALKING ABOUT THAT
GIRL
YOU SAID YOU HAVE A DATE WITH.
- ALL RIGHT, SO I LIED.
IT WASN'T A DATE.
- BUT YOU COULD HAVE
MADE ONE WITH HER.
I THINK THAT POPPINS KNOCKED THE
COURAGE OUT OF YOU.
- I GUESS I'M JUST NOT
IN HER LEAGUE.
HOW DID YOU
HEAR ABOUT THE POPPINS?
- IT WAS ON THE NEWS.
- announcer: AN UNLICENSED MARY
POPPINS
TAKES DOWN ANOTHER TOURIST.
IS THIS THE WORK
OF THE ITSY BITSY I.R.A.?
- I DON'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT THIS RIGHT NOW.
DAD, WE'RE GONNA GO IN THERE.
ANDY GRIFFITH'S GONNA
WHISPER SOMETHING.
WE'RE GONNA PLEAD GUILTY.
NICE AND SIMPLE.
- YOU DIDN'T HEAR.
WE LOST ANDY.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- HE DIDN'T LIKE HIS TRAILER.
- HE THOUGHT WE WERE
MAKING FUN OF HIM.
narrator: NO ONE WAS MAKING FUN
OF ANDY GRIFFITH.
I CAN'T EMPHASIZE THAT ENOUGH.
[rock music]
- OH, GOD. DON'T LOOK NOW,
BUT GOB'S DOING
HIS MAGIC SHOW.
- OH, BOY.
A STUPID MAGIC SHOW.
WE GOTTA WATCH THIS.
- A BIG TURNOUT.
- I THINK LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
PROBABLY HERE
FOR THE FREE CHICKEN.
- GATHER ROUND, HUMANS,
AND I WILL SHOW YOU
THE PLIGHT...
OF AN INNOCENT MAN
WHO YEARNS TO BE...
FREE AS A BIRD!
[coins clanking]
I'VE GOTTA START
LABELING THESE SUITS.
WHO SHALL I SEND
ON THIS JOURNEY...
TO THAT DANGLING CAGE?
- OH, PICK ME.
LOOK, COULD I BE
IN THIS STUPID TRICK?
PLEASE?
- STEVE HOLT, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
- I-I JUST CAME
TO SEE THE MAGIC SHOW.
I DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS YOU.
- DO YOU LIKE MAGIC?
- NO.
I LOVE IT.
- narrator:
AND AT THAT MOMENT,
GOB CHOSE TO SHOW HIS OWN SON
WHAT HE WAS CAPABLE OF.
I'VE DECIDED I WILL BE
PERFORMING THE FEAT...
MYSELF.
- WAIT. WE'RE BACK TO HAIR?
narrator: FORTUNATELY FOR
TOBIAS, HOWEVER,
HE'D FOUND IT TOO PAINFUL
TO PART WITH HIS NEW HAIR.
- [screams]
BOY.
DID I CATCH A BREAK.
SO HE OPTED TO WEAR
A BALD CAP.
- THIS CHICKEN...
SHALL BE WRONGLY COOPED.
- IS THAT A CHICKEN?
OH, MY GOD.
- DAD, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I FOOLED HIS OWN SON.
I AM A LEADING MAN.
[imitates chicken]
narrator: AND GOB HIMSELF WAS
RUNNING THROUGH THE STORM
DRAINS--
- [sobbing]
I'M SORRY, STEVE.
narrator: FREE AS A CHICKEN.
- I NEED TO BE A FATHER.
- [imitates chicken]
narrator: AND GEORGE SR. NEEDED
TO ESCAPE TOO.
- I GOT HIM.
[stun gun zaps]
KEEPS HIM OUT OF THE KITCHEN.
narrator: AND MICHAEL,
SEEING WHAT
A LIFE OF COWARDICE LEADS TO,
DECIDED HE'D HAD
ENOUGH OF IT.
AND SOON GEORGE SR. CAME TO,
AND IT WAS TIME...
TO RENDER A PLEA.
- OH, NO.
PROSECUTION'S GOT THAT STUD
FROM L.A. LAW.
- IT'S HARRY HAMLIN.
- I LOVE MY TRAILER.
- IN THE MATTER OF
THE PEOPLE V. BLUTH,
HOW DO YOU PLEAD?
- WE PLEAD...NOT GUILTY.
- [woman gasps]
- ORDER IN THE COURT!
- WHO LET A FLASHBULB CAMERA IN?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I'M TIRED OF THE COWARDICE.
YOU'RE NOT GUILTY.
WE'RE GONNA FIGHT THIS.
- THEY DON'T HAVE
A-- [bleep] PRAYER.
SEND THE CHECK
TO MY ACCOUNTANT.
- THIS IS WHERE ANDY
COULD HAVE HELPED US.
- WELL, I'M PROUD OF YOU.
- IT'S ABOUT TIME
I SHOWED A LITTLE COURAGE.
- I JUST HOPE THOSE BRITS AREN'T
AS DANGEROUS AS DAD SAID.
- WELL, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
GET ANY CLOSER TO US.
IF THEY DO,
WE'RE GONNA SEE THEM COMING.
OH, MY GOD.
THAT'S RITA.
I TOLD HER I WAS COMING HERE
AND SHE CAME.
- THAT'S RITA?
- YEAH.
- WOW. SHE IS WAY
OUT OF HIS LEAGUE.
- I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
I WANNA CALL YOU SOMETIME
AND TAKE YOU OUT.
- OH.
I'D REALLY LIKE THAT.
narrator: AND THEN,
JUST TO PROVE TO HIMSELF HE
WASN'T A COWARD,
HE WENT ONE STEP FURTHER.
AND RITA WAS HAPPY TO BE IN
MICHAEL'S LIFE AS WELL.
FOR YOU SEE, RITA
HAD A SECRET OF HER OWN.
- [singing]
FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY
[tires squealing]