narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH AND HIS FAMILY
WERE MEETING
WITH THEIR NEW ATTORNEY.
- LOOK, THIS IS NOT THE FIRST
TIME I'VE BEEN BROUGHT IN
TO REPLACE BARRY ZUCKERKORN.
I THINK I CAN DO FOR YOU
EVERYTHING HE DID,
PLUS SKEW YOUNGER
WITH JURIES AND SO FORTH.
ANY OTHER QUESTIONS?
- YES. HOW CAN YOU BE
EVEN CUTER IN PERSON
THAN YOU ARE IN YOUR ADS?
- ARE YOU A C.E.O., C.F.O.
OR OTHER EXECUTIVE
FACING THESE
OR SIMILAR CHARGES?
- WHY SHOULD YOU GO TO JAIL FOR
A CRIME SOMEONE ELSE NOTICED?
YOU DON'T NEED DOUBLE-TALK.
YOU NEED BOB LOBLAW.
- BOB LOBLAW NO HABLA ESPANOL.
- WELL, WE'RE NOT HERE TO TALK
NONSENSE TO BOB LOBLAW.
WE NEED TO FIND OUT
IF THE GOVERNMENT HAS
A GOOD CASE AGAINST US.
I MEAN, THERE IS
A LOT OF PROOF
THAT MY FATHER
WAS BUILDING HOUSES IN IRAQ.
- WELL, YOUR FATHER CLAIMS
HE WAS PUT UP TO IT
BY A BRITISH SYNDICATE.
AND YOU'VE BEEN THREATENED.
ISN'T THAT CORRECT?
narrator: IT WAS.
- HOW WOULD YOU LIKE SOMEONE
GOING AFTER SOME STUPID PERSON
IN YOUR FAMILY?
NOW, BACK OFF,
YOU [bleep] PONCE!
- IT'S BEEN A WEEK.
NOTHING'S HAPPENED.
- YEAH, BUT YOU'RE NOT THE ONE
STUCK UNDER HOUSE ARREST
LIKE A SITTING DUCK.
- OH, YEAH.
THAT'S MY FATHER.
THAT'S WHY WE HAD THE MEETING
HERE--SO HE COULDN'T INTERFERE.
- INTERFERE?
I OUGHTA PULL DOWN YOUR PANTS
AND SPANK YOUR ASS RAW.
- I'M SORRY.
HAVE WE MET?
- OH, YES.
THIS IS LARRY MIDDLEMAN.
HE'S YOUR FATHER'S SURROGATE.
- SURROGATE?
- THAT'S RIGHT,
YOU DUMB [bleep].
- I HIRED THIS GUY TO WEAR
A CAMERA IN HIS HAT
SO HE COULD BE MY EYES
AND EARS
WHILE I'M STUCK
IN THIS PENTHOUSE.
- THIS CAMERA HELPS ME
KEEP TABS ON YOU IDIOTS
WHILE THIS THING
RUBS MY ANKLE RAW.
- I MEAN, LOOK AT THIS THING.
- I CAN'T EVEN GO
IN THE HALLWAY--
- WITHOUT HEARING THAT--
- BEEP, BEEP, BEEP.
- THAT'S ONE OF MY PARTNERS.
EXCUSE ME.
- UH, I-I WOULD LIKE TO BE
ONE OF YOUR PARTNERS.
DO YOU THINK HE GOT THAT?
TH-THE TWO MEANINGS?
- HE'S RUNNING PRETTY FAST.
I THINK HE DID.
- WELL, HE WAS FLIRTING EARLIER.
I'LL TELL YOU THAT.
JUST SO YOU KNOW,
I'M LOOKING TO GET DIVORCED.
ARE YOU INTERESTED?
- YES.
LET'S CALL THAT A HALF HOUR.
- SO YOU'RE NOT THE ONLY ONE
WHO'S GOT A DATE LATER.
- YOU'VE GOT A DATE?
- HER NAME'S RITA.
SHE TEACHES CHILDREN
AT A PRIVATE SCHOOL,
AND WE'RE JUST HAVING LUNCH.
- OH, LUNCH. WELL, BETTER
BRING SOME DOG FOOD.
'CAUSE ALL THE GIRLS YOU DATE
ARE DOGS.
DOGS LOVE DOG FOOD,
RIGHT, POP?
- SHUT UP, YOU IDIOT.
I'M TRYING TO WATCH THE GAME.
- JUST TRYING
TO MAKE YOU LAUGH, DAD.
IT'S ALL I EVER WANT.
- SMITH THE CATCHER--
- YOU KNOW, GOB,
SHE'S NOT A DOG.
IT'S JUST THE OPPOSITE ACTUALLY.
SHE'S EXQUISITELY BEAUTIFUL.
SHE'S FUN, CAREFREE, SMART,
FULL OF SURPRISES.
narrator: INCLUDING THE FACT
THAT SHE WAS WORKING
WITH THIS MAN,
WHO WAS CURRENTLY
DROPPING HER OFF FOR HER DATE.
- NOW ALL THIS FUN
AND CAREFREE ACT
IS ONLY GONNA FOOL HIM
FOR SO LONG.
- I'M A BIG GIRL.
- YEAH. WELL, IF HE FINDS OUT
WHAT YOU REALLY ARE,
HE MIGHT NOT MAKE THINGS
SO SIMPLE FOR YOU.
RITA, DON'T FORGET YOUR HAT.
- AND WHO AM I KIDDING?
SHE'S TOO GOOD FOR ME.
- HOW DO YOU THINK I FEEL?
BOB LOBLAW'S A HANDSOME,
PROFESSIONAL MAN,
AND I'M ONLY USED TO--
WELL, NONE OF THOSE THINGS.
- OKAY, LINDSAY,
ARE YOU FORGETTING
THAT I WAS
A PROFESSIONAL TWICE OVER?
AN ANALYST AND A THERAPIST.
THE WORLD'S FIRST "ANALRAPIST."
- YES, AND YOU
WERE ALMOST ARRESTED
FOR THOSE BUSINESS CARDS.
- YES. NO, IT DID NOT LOOK GOOD
ON PAPER,
BUT I DIDN'T STOP BECAUSE
OF THE POLICE INQUIRIES.
I STOPPED TO RAISE
OUR LITTLE DAUGHTER.
BUT SINCE WE BOTH
HAVE STARTED TO GROW HAIR
IN UNEXPECTED PLACES,
I SUPPOSE I SHALL SOON
BE WORKING AS A LEADING MAN,
AND SHE MAY SOON
START DATING.
narrator: MAEBY HAD ALREADY
STARTED DATING.
- ANOTHER DATE
WITH, UH, STEVE HOLT?
- YEAH. WE'RE GETTIN'
PRETTY SERIOUS.
narrator: THEY WEREN'T.
SHE WAS JUST AVOIDING HER
REAL CRUSH ON GEORGE MICHAEL.
- THAT STEVE SURE KNOWS
HOW TO PLEASE A LADY.
- GOOD. I WAS HOPING
HE WOULD BE GIFTED SEXUALLY.
I MEAN, I GUESS IT MAKES SENSE.
YOU KNOW, UH, OLDER GUYS
EXPECT CERTAIN THINGS.
- THEY DO?
- WHAT A FUN, SEXY TIME FOR YOU.
- I'D BE VERY CAREFUL
OF THESE BRITISH PEOPLE.
THEY'RE GONNA TRY TO GET
THEIR HANDS
ON ANY EVIDENCE
THEY CAN TO HURT THE FAMILY.
- SO YOU'RE SAYING
SHRED THE EVIDENCE?
- NO, THAT'S ILLEGAL.
THE PROSECUTION IS ENTITLED
TO THAT EVIDENCE.
WITHOUT IT,
THEY DON'T HAVE A CASE.
- SO YOU'RE SAYING
SHRED THE EVIDENCE?
- THAT'S A FELONY.
AND I CERTAINLY COULDN'T
ENDORSE ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
- GOT YA. WINK.
- WINK. DID YOU SAY WINK?
OR DID YOU WINK?
- HE SAID THAT TOO, DAD.
- WE'LL TALK SOON, FOLKS.
THANK YOU.
- WHERE YOU GOING?
WHERE IS THE SURROGATE GOING?
STAY THERE. I WANT TO SEE WHAT
HE'S GONNA SAY. DON'T LEAVE.
- SEE YA, POP.
- YOU KNOW, GOB,
INSTEAD OF TRYING TO IMPRESS
YOUR FAKE FATHER,
MAYBE YOU SHOULD SPEND
SOME TIME WITH YOUR REAL SON.
- STEVE HOLT'S NOT MY SON.
- STEVE HOLT?
THE MORON JOCK?
- THAT'S MY SON,
YOU POTHEAD.
- HEY, THAT'S MY SON!
- WAIT. SO THAT MEANS THAT
STEVE HOLT IS MY COUSIN?
AND MAEBY'S COUSIN TOO.
- I GUESS. SHOOT,
I'M LATE FOR MY DATE.
- YEAH. AT THE KENNEL!
[laughs]
[door opens, closes]
SORRY, YOU LOBBED THAT ONE
RIGHT OVER THE PLATE, MICHAEL.
HOME RUN.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL HURRIED
TO THE BRITISH SECTION
OF ORANGE COUNTY FOR HIS DATE.
- CRAZY AMERICAN!
GET OUT OF THE ROAD!
narrator: ONLY TO FIND
THAT RITA HAD CHOSEN
WEE BRITAIN'S
ONE AMERICAN-THEMED RESTAURANT.
- OH, HELLO.
I'M SORRY I'M LATE.
- OH, NO BOTHER.
I'VE BEEN HAVING
SUCH FUN ON THIS SPACESHIP.
- STRIKE ONE, HUH?
SHALL WE GO AHEAD AND SIT DOWN?
- HEY, DUDES, I'LL GET YOU
A COUPLE OF 64-OUNCE COLAS
TO WASH DOWN
THIS BASKET OF DOUGHNUTS
AND GET YOUR NACHOS--
- I GUESS THIS IS WHAT
THE BRITISH THINK OF AMERICANS.
WE LIKE OUR FOOD.
- WHATEVER DO YOU MEAN?
- [laughs]
YEAH.
UH, YOU KNOW, UH, RITA,
YOU'RE GONNA FIGURE THIS OUT
EVENTUALLY,
BUT I HAVE NOT BEEN ON A DATE
IN A LONG, LONG TIME.
- NEITHER HAVE I.
- I WONDER WHY.
I'LL BET MEN
ASK YOU OUT CONSTANTLY.
- NOT MEN LIKE YOU. I SEEM
TO ONLY MEET LITTLE BOYS.
- PART OF THAT MIGHT BE THAT YOU
SPEND YOUR DAY AT A PRESCHOOL.
[laughing]
- AND THEY THINK THE STUPIDEST
THINGS ARE FUNNY.
- YEAH, THAT'S A CULTURAL
PROBLEM IS WHAT IT IS, YOU KNOW.
YOUR AVERAGE AMERICAN MALE
IS IN A PERPETUAL
STATE OF ADOLESCENCE--
YOU KNOW,
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
narrator: HEY, THAT'S THE NAME
OF THE SHOW!
- NO ATTENTION SPAN.
YOU KNOW, CAN'T EVEN
CARRY ON A TYPICAL CONV--
narrator: MICHAEL THOUGHT
HE SPOTTED THE MAN
WHO'D THREATENED HIM EARLIER.
- WELL, I'M GETTIN' BACK
ON THE SPACE SHUTTLE.
- NO, NO, NO. SORRY. SORRY.
SIT, PLEASE.
LET'S TALK ABOUT YOU.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
- WELL, THEY'RE PUSHY, BOSSY,
WANT TO CONTROL ME.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR FAMILY?
I'D LOVE TO MEET YOUR FAMILY.
narrator:
MICHAEL KNEW FROM EXPERIENCE
THAT THIS
WOULD NOT TURN OUT WELL.
- ONCE OR TWICE A WEEK,
WE GET A--
[continues, indistinct]
HAVE A LITTLE MORE.
- IF YOU LIKE THE SMALL,
WHY DON'T YOU COME BACK
FOR THE MEDIUM?
[laughing]
- [indistinct] RIGHT?
YOU CAN SEE THAT, RIGHT?
I PROBABLY SHOULD WARN YOU
ABOUT MY MOTHER.
- HI.
- LET'S START BEHIND THE FRIDGE.
narrator: SO HE CAME UP WITH
A SOLUTION SO SIMPLE,
HE WONDERED WHY HE'D
NEVER TOLD ANYONE IT BEFORE.
- I DON'T HAVE A FAMILY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I'VE NEVER
TOLD ANYBODY THAT BEFORE.
- THAT'S SO SAD.
- YES, SAD. SUPER SAD.
SHALL WE EAT?
narrator: MICHAEL HAD STARTED
A RELATIONSHIP
BY LYING ABOUT THE EXISTENCE
OF HIS FAMILY.
- I THINK THIS WENT
REALLY WELL, HUH?
MAYBE SOMETIME
WE CAN HAVE DINNER?
- COULD I SEE YOUR HOUSE?
narrator: MICHAEL WAS CAUGHT
OFF-GUARD BY THE QUESTION.
- NO. NO. I-I--
I CAN'T DO THAT.
- OKAY, BYE-BYE.
- UH, BYE.
narrator: AND HE VOWED NOT TO BE
CAUGHT OFF-GUARD AGAIN.
- I DIDN'T MEAN THAT WE--
[grunts]
- SO DID HE INVITE YOU
OVER, THEN?
- NOT YET, BUT HE WILL.
narrator: SO MICHAEL
WENT BACK TO WORK.
[machines whirring]
- HEY, WHO BROUGHT IN
THE WOOD--
GOB, YOU CAN'T SHRED
THIS EVIDENCE.
YOU'LL END UP IN JAIL.
- DAD TOLD ME TO.
HOW CAN I SAY NO
TO THAT FACE?
- GET THIS STUFF OUT OF HERE
AND PUT IT SOMEWHERE
WHERE DAD CAN'T GET TO IT.
ARE YOU IN ON THIS TOO?
- NO, I'M JUST HERE TO GO OUT
TO LUNCH WITH YOUR FATHER.
- AND HE SAID HE'S NEVER FELT
MORE FREE IN HIS LIFE.
- I'M LIKE A BIRD UP THERE.
- DID YOU TELL HIM
ABOUT MY MEDAL?
- MEDAL? WHAT FOR?
- OH, WHO KNOWS WHAT
THEY WERE SAYING.
- [rapid muttering]
DO YOU AGREE?
SAY THANK YOU.
- THANK YOU. WOW.
I HAVE SO MANY PEOPLE
TO THANK.
- PRIVATE ASHER, STEP FORWARD!
- IT'S PROBABLY BECAUSE
A SEAL BIT OFF HIS HAND.
THE ARMY HAS TAKEN TO GIVING
MEDALS FOR BEING FOOD.
- HUH.
narrator: JUST THEN--
- WOW, LOOK AT HIM GO
TIED TO THAT DECK CHAIR!
- IT'S SO SIMPLE.
MY ANKLE MONITOR--
- ONLY GOES OFF WHEN
I GO OUT THE FRONT DOOR.
WE NEED BALLOONS.
A PARTY!
- WE NEED TO THROW A PARTY FOR--
- BUSTER'S STUPID THING.
LARRY, GO GET SOME BALLOONS.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
FOUND A WAY
TO GET RITA
TO HIS HOUSE AFTER ALL.
- THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
HONOR BUSTER TOMORROW NIGHT.
WE'LL GET THE WHOLE FAMILY
OVER TO THE PENTHOUSE,
SHOW HIM OUR SUPPORT.
- WELL, I SUPPOSE IT'S BETTER
THAN DRINKING ALONE.
WHAT TIME?
- DOESN'T MATTER TO ME.
I CAN'T BE THERE.
I'VE GOT A DATE WITH RITA.
- [chuckles]
WELL, MOM'S PROBABLY RIGHT.
I COULDN'T EVEN
STAND UP TO A SEAL.
I DON'T REALLY DESERVE
A MEDAL OR A PARTY.
- NO, YOU DESERVE THIS.
HERE, TAKE MY BUSINESS CARD.
- [gasps]
- NO, NO. IT'S PRONOUNCED
"A-NALRA-PIST."
- IT WASN'T REALLY THE
PRONUNCIATION THAT BOTHERED ME.
- YOU SEE, BUSTER,
IT WASN'T THE SEAL THAT
YOU COULDN'T STAND UP TO.
IT WAS LUCILLE.
- [gasps]
OH, I'M GETTING CHILLS.
IF THIS WAS A LIFETIME
MOMENT OF TRUTH MOVIE,
THIS WOULD BE
OUR ACT BREAK.
[banjo]
narrator:
BUT IT WASN'T.
AND LATER, LINDSAY WAS
ON THE PHONE WITH BOB LOBLAW.
- I LOVE TOBIAS, BUT HE'S
NEVER FULFILLED ME SEXUALLY.
- CAN YOU CATALOG FOR ME
THE VARIOUS WAYS
YOU'VE BEEN
PROMISED TO BE FULFILLED,
WHETHER OR NOT SAID PROMISE
WAS MADE EXPLICIT?
- YOU WANT ME TO BE EXPLICIT?
- YES.
BUT I WILL BE NEEDING
TO GET OFF IN FOUR MINUTES.
- WELL, LET'S SEE IF I CAN'T
HIT THAT TARGET FOR YOU.
narrator: THE NEXT DAY,
ON THE WAY TO PICK UP RITA,
MICHAEL STOPPED BY HIS HOUSE
TO MAKE SURE THERE WERE
NO SIGNS OF HIS FAMILY,
ONLY TO DISCOVER
THERE WAS NOTHING BUT.
- WHAT THE HELL IS ALL THIS?
- OH, GOB
BROUGHT ALL THIS STUFF IN.
- AND, MOM, WHAT IS WITH
ALL THE FAMILY PHOTOS?
- OH, I'M TEACHING BUSTER
TO STAND UP FOR HIMSELF.
I'M SURROGATING YOUR MOTHER.
- BY WEARING
HER SEALSKIN COAT?
- MICHAEL, I HAVE TRIED ON
EVERYTHING,
AND NOTHING
SEEMS TO BE WORKING.
- I THOUGHT
THE DONNA KARAN WORKED.
YOU JUST DIDN'T
HAVE THE RIGHT SHOES.
- LOOK, I'VE GOTTA GET RID
OF ANY EVIDENCE OF MY FAMILY,
AND QUICKLY
INCLUDING YOU GUYS.
GET OUTTA HERE!
- SEE? NOW, THAT'S HOW
YOU STAND UP TO MOTHER.
- GET OUT OF HERE!
narrator: MEANWHILE,
WORRIED ABOUT STEVE HOLT'S
SEXUAL EXPECTATIONS,
MAEBY TRIED TO CANCEL HER DATE.
- MY WHOLE FAMILY AND I NOW HAVE
TO GO TO MY GRANDMA'S HOUSE
BECAUSE MY UNCLE
LOST HIS HAND.
- AWESOME!
SO YOU AND I CAN PARTY
ALONE AT YOUR HOUSE.
narrator: MAEBY WAS TOO YOUNG
TO KNOW WHAT TO DO.
IRONICALLY, IN HER AFTER-SCHOOL
JOB AS A MOVIE STUDIO EXECUTIVE,
SHE'D JUST GREEN-LIT TWO FILMS
THAT DEALT WITH THE VERY ISSUE.
- ROCK THE HOUSE.
- ALL RIGHT.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL ALSO
DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
IF HE POINTED OUT
THAT THE TWO WERE COUSINS
TO DRIVE THEM APART,
HE MIGHT BE BURNING
THE VERY BRIDGE
THAT HE ONE DAY
HOPED TO CROSS.
- I'M DOING
YOUR COUSIN TONIGHT.
- SO ARE YOU.
- WHAT?
- SHE'S YOUR COUSIN TOO.
narrator: BACK AT THE PENTHOUSE,
PARTY PREPARATIONS
WERE UNDERWAY.
- HE'S NOT WEARING THAT
TO THE PARTY.
I'VE GOT
THE EXACT SAME THING.
- NO, HE WAS JUST
ANALRAPING ME.
THEN MICHAEL BARGED IN
AND KICKED US OUT
SO HE COULD SHRED
ALL THE EVIDENCE.
- SHRED THE EVIDENCE?
- I THOUGHT HE DIDN'T
WANT US TO DO THAT.
- HE DIDN'T WANT US
TO GET INTO TROUBLE.
HE'S TAKING THE HEAT.
- HE'S DOING THAT FOR US?
AND ON THE NIGHT
OF HIS DATE WITH RITA.
- WHO HE DIDN'T WANT
TO BRING OVER HERE.
PROBABLY BECAUSE--
LET'S FACE IT--
YOU PEOPLE HAVEN'T BEEN
GREAT WITH THE OTHERS.
- WELL, IN OUR DEFENSE, MOM,
WE'RE NOT EXACTLY DOG PEOPLE.
- WE HAVE GOT TO START
BEING NICER.
- I'M STARTING RIGHT NOW.
BUSTER, THE PARTY'S
NOT FOR YOU ANYMORE.
- OH, OKAY.
- IT'S A "WELCOME RITA" PARTY.
- I KNOW WHERE SHE WORKS.
WE CAN PICK HER UP
AND SURPRISE HER.
- YOU'RE SO RIGHT.
THIS IS BETTER
THAN A PARTY FOR ME.
- OH, COME ON.
GROW A PAIR.
- YOU KNOW, WE NEED SOME WEATHER
BALLOONS FOR THIS PARTY,
AND MAYBE A TANK OF HYDROGEN.
[thud, car alarm blaring]
YOU KNOW, REALLY
FLOAT THOSE SUCKERS.
narrator: MEANWHILE, MICHAEL
WAS HIDING THE EVIDENCE
WHEREVER HE COULD
WHEN HE HEARD FROM HIS BROTHER.
- HEY, FRIEND. GOB HERE.
WE REALLY WANT YOU AT THE PARTY.
WE'RE REALLY NICE NOW.
AND, GOD, WE LOVE YOU.
- [sighs]
DAMN IT.
narrator: AND THE FAMILY PICKED
UP RITA IN THE ONLY VEHICLE
BIG ENOUGH TO HOLD THEM ALL.
- HEY, HEY.
EXCUSE ME. RITA?
- I'M RITA.
- WE'RE HERE TO PICK YOU UP
FOR MICHAEL.
UH, YOU CAN JUST
GO IN THE CABIN.
- MICHAEL?
- OH, HE'S NOT HERE.
WE'RE HIS FAMILY.
- OH, HIS FAMILY.
- WE'RE NICE.
- I'M SORRY. I HAVE TO LEAVE.
- OH, NO, YOU CANNOT LEAVE.
DRIVE, LINDSAY!
- [children] BYE!
- WE'RE DOING THIS FOR MICHAEL.
- STOP HER, BUSTER.
- WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
- STOP HER!
- STOP YELLING AT ME!
- I'M LEAVING!
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN BUSTER NOTICED
THE SEAL ON RITA'S BACKPACK.
- [screaming]
[whimpering]
- HEY, TALK ABOUT CATHARTIC.
NOW THAT'S AN ACT BREAK.
[banjo]
narrator: BUSTER HAD OVERCOME
HIS FEAR OF SEALS.
UNFORTUNATELY, HE'D DONE SO
BY KNOCKING OUT
MICHAEL'S NEW GIRLFRIEND.
- WHAT THE HELL DID YOU DO?
- YOU CURIOUS, MOM?
I CAN SHOW YOU.
- UH, YOU MADE A MISTAKE.
YOU'RE HUMAN.
EXCEPT FOR THE HAND.
- IT'S OKAY. SHE'S ALIVE.
AND SOFT. SOFT AND ALIVE.
- ALL RIGHT, LET'S NOT
ADD THAT TO THE CHARGES.
WHAT'LL WE DO?
SHE'S GONNA TELL MICHAEL.
AND HE WON'T HEAR
THE GOOD STUFF.
HE'LL JUST HEAR
ABOUT THE BEATING.
- WAIT. MAYBE WE CAN GIVE HER
A "FORGET-ME-NOW."
HERE YOU GO, HOT DOG.
TAKE THE PILL.
- WHAT'S A FORGET-ME-NOW?
- THEY'RE PILLS THAT CREATE
A SORT OF TEMPORARY
"FORGETTINESS."
SO IF SOMEBODY FINDS OUT
HOW YOU DO A TRICK,
YOU JUST GIVE THEM ONE OF THESE,
AND THEY FORGET THE WHOLE THING.
IT'S A MAINSTAY
OF THE MAGICIAN'S TOOL KIT.
LIKE HOW CLOWNS ALWAYS HAVE
A RAG SOAKED IN ETHER.
- GOB, THIS IS FLUNITRAZIPAM.
IT'S A ROOFIE.
- THOSE ARE ILLEGAL!
- SHUT UP, MOM.
DON'T MAKE ME GIVE YOU
ANOTHER ONE OF THESE.
- [gasps]
- LINDSAY, HELP ME!
THREE!
narrator: BACK AT THE HOUSE,
MICHAEL FINISHED HIS WORK
AND NOW LATE,
RUSHED TO PICK UP RITA.
MOMENTS LATER,
MAEBY PREPARED TO TELL STEVE
SHE WASN'T READY FOR ROMANCE.
- WELL, THIS SENDS
A MIXED MESSAGE.
narrator: JUST AS STEVE
SHOWED UP
TO CALL THINGS OFF
WITH HIS COUSIN.
- YOU DID ALL THIS FOR ME?
- YES.
WELL, I'M GONNA
GO GET SEXY.
narrator:
AND MICHAEL MISSED RITA.
- DAMN IT. STRIKE TWO.
[phone rings]
- TAKE IT DOWN.
WE DON'T WANT ANYTHING
IN THIS HOUSE THAT SAYS RITA.
- HI. IT'S MICHAEL.
I WILL BE COMING TO THE PARTY,
BECAUSE I LOVE YOU TOO.
- OKAY. WE NEED A NEW BANNER.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN MICHAEL FOUND RITA.
- RITA.
- WHY AM I ON A BUS BENCH,
MICHAEL?
- I GET IT.
BECAUSE I'M LATE.
I'M SORRY. BUT THE REST
OF THE NIGHT'S
GONNA BE ALL ABOUT YOU,
I PROMISE.
GREAT. GREAT.
I AM GONNA HAVE TO MAKE
ONE QUICK STOP.
MAYBE JUST WAIT
IN THE CAR?
IT'S JUST GONNA BE
TWO SECONDS, I PROMISE.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL
RACED UP
TO PAY HIS QUICK RESPECTS
TO BUSTER.
- AH, THERE HE IS--
MY FAVORITE SON.
- EVERYBODY'S
FAVORITE SON!
- MR. WONDERFUL!
[growls]
- WELL, I HAD A GREAT TIME.
I WISH I COULD'VE STAYED LONGER.
THIS IS A GREAT PARTY, HUH?
TELL BUSTER I STOPPED BY,
PLEASE.
I DO HAVE TO LEAVE.
- OH, NO, NO, NO.
THE PARTY IS NOT
FOR BUSTER ANYMORE.
- NO, MICHAEL.
IT'S FOR YOU.
- ME.
- TAKE A LOOK
AT BANNER, MICHAEL!
- YOU GUYS DID ALL OF THIS
FOR ME? "FAMILY LOVE--"
- MICHAEL?
narrator:
EVERYONE FROZE.
MICHAEL FEARED HE'D BEEN CAUGHT
IN A LIE ABOUT HIS FAMILY.
HIS FAMILY FEARED
THEY'D BEEN CAUGHT
BY A WOMAN THEY CLUBBED,
DRUGGED, AND LEFT ON A BENCH.
IT WAS AWKWARD.
- WHO'S THIS?
- MOTHER! MOTHER!
THIS IS FROM THE ARMY.
I HAVE TO REPORT
FOR DUTY TOMORROW!
IT SAYS BY ACCEPTING THIS
MEDAL, I WAS REENLISTING.
- I DIDN'T HEAR THEM
SAY THAT.
narrator: PERHAPS IF THE
SERGEANT HAD SPOKEN MORE SLOWLY,
SHE WOULD HAVE.
- [slow motion]
IN ACCEPTANCE OF THIS MEDAL,
YOU PROUDLY WAIVE ALL RIGHTS
TO PRIVATE CITIZENSHIP
AND HEREBY REENLIST IN THE ARMED
SERVICES OF THE UNITED STATES.
IF YOU AGREE WITH THIS,
SAY THANK YOU.
- [very slow motion]
THANK YOU.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
I CAN'T GO BACK THERE.
I'VE NEVER BEEN!
- WHO ARE THESE PEOPLE?
- THIS IS MY FAMILY.
- NO. NO.
I DON'T LIKE THESE PEOPLE.
- ME. YOU MEAN--SHE MEANS ME.
BECAUSE I LIED
ABOUT HAVING A FAMILY,
BECAUSE I WAS EMBARRASSED
BY THEM.
AND I'M ASHAMED OF THAT.
- I HAVE TO LEAVE.
- STRIKE THREE.
- YOU SAID YOU DIDN'T
HAVE A FAMILY?
- EVERYBODY'S
FAVORITE SON.
- MR. TERRIBLE.
- AND HER?
TOO GOOD FOR US? HUH.
BUSTER, YOU SHOULD'VE
FINISHED THE JOB.
- JOB? WHAT JOB?
- DID I SAY JOB? I MEANT GOB.
- BUSTER'S THE ONE THAT HIT HER.
I JUST GAVE HER THE ROOFIE.
- ROOFIE?
- FORGET-ME-NOW.
- YOU BEAT AND DRUGGED RITA?
- TAKE THIS
AND LOVE US AGAIN.
- NO, NO, NO!
- NO, JUST TAKE IT!
- NO, GOB!
UM, I'M LEAVING TOO.
- WELL, NO GOOD DEED
GOES UNPUNISHED.
- OH, LOOK,
IT'S NOT ALL BAD.
I--I GOT BUSTER FEELING
BETTER ABOUT HIS MEDAL.
- NOT ANYMORE.
I'M GETTING RID OF THIS THING.
IT HAS CAUSED ME NOTHING
BUT PRIDE AND SELF-RESPECT!
narrator: BUSTER WENT TO GET RID
OF THE MEDAL
HE FINALLY FELT HE DESERVED,
BUT IT WAS EXACTLY WHEN GEORGE
SR. WAS MAKING HIS ESCAPE.
- FAREWELL TO YOU ALL!
- [yells, screams]
narrator: BUT IT TURNS OUT
THAT HYDROGEN
IS MORE EXPLOSIVE THAN HELIUM.
- [grunting, shouting]
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
CAME HOME
TO FIND
AN UNCONSCIOUS STEVE HOLT.
- WHAT HAVE YOU GUYS
BEEN DOING?
- I GAVE HIM A ROOFIE.
A GIRL'S GOTTA GROW UP
SOMETIME.
- HE'S YOUR COUSIN!
- MY COUSIN?
- I SHOULD HAVE TOLD YOU THAT.
NOW YOU'VE DRUGGED HIM
AND HAD YOUR WAY WITH HIM.
HOW IS THAT EVEN POSSIBLE?
- NO, GEORGE MICHAEL.
WE DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
I JUST WANTED HIM TO THINK
WE DID. DON'T YOU SEE?
I DRUGGED HIM NOT TO GO
ALL THE WAY WITH HIM.
- WELL, I THINK
EVEN THE ANTIDRUG PEOPLE
ARE GONNA BE OKAY WITH THAT.
- WELL, LET'S GET
HIS PANTS BACK ON.
- YOU TOOK HIS PANTS OFF?
narrator:
AND MICHAEL TRIED TO SALVAGE
THE REMAINS OF THE FILES
FROM THE CAR FIRE.
- YOU CALL THE ATTORNEY?
- YEAH, I SURE DID, BUT HE'S
NOT TAKING OUR CALLS,
BECAUSE APPARENTLY
THE RETAINER IS ALL USED UP.
- HE TOOK MY CALL.
HE'S VERY GOOD.
- YEAH, THAT'S HOW THE RETAINER
GOT EATEN UP, OKAY?
THE SECRETARY TOOK IT ALL
DOWN HERE ON A TRANSCRIPT.
- UGH. SHE'S VERY GOOD TOO.
- I'M NOT PAYING FOR THIS.
- WELL, WHAT AM I
SUPPOSED TO DO?
- I DON'T KNOW, LINDSAY.
THING YOU SAY ON PAGE SEVEN
LOOKS LIKE
IT COULD BE WORTH SOME MONEY.
- SPEAKING TO ME YET?
- IT'S ONLY BEEN AN HOUR.
HERE'S WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT WERE YOU GUYS DOING
WITH RITA IN THE FIRST PLACE?
- WE JUST WANTED TO DO SOMETHING
NICE FOR YOU, MICHAEL,
'CAUSE YOU DO
SO MUCH FOR US.
I GUESS
WE SCREWED IT UP.
- NO, I SCREWED IT UP, 'CAUSE
I WAS TRYING TO IMPRESS HER.
LET'S FACE IT.
SHE'S PROBABLY TOO GOOD FOR ME.
- NO. WHAT YOU NEED TO DO
IS GO TO HER
AND ASK
FOR ANOTHER CHANCE.
SHE'D BE LUCKY
TO HAVE YOU, MICHAEL.
- THANKS, GOB.
SOMETIMES
YOU DO SURPRISE ME.
- I'VE GOT ONE MORE
SURPRISE FOR YOU.
- [singing]
IT AIN'T EASY BEIN'--
narrator: AND MICHAEL DID TRY
AGAIN WITH RITA,
BUT THIS TIME DETERMINED
TO KEEP NO SECRETS.
- I WANNA TELL YOU EVERYTHING,
IF--IF YOU'RE WILLING
TO LISTEN.
- I'M A VERY GOOD LISTENER.
- GREAT. WE'LL START
WITH THE MISDEMEANORS,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUSH
RIGHT ON THROUGH
TO THE LIGHTER TREASONS.
SO 1983--
- [singing]
FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
LINDSAY TRIES TO WORK OFF
HER DEBT WITH BOB LOBLAW.
- I'M WILLING
TO DEBASE MYSELF.
- GET A MAID'S UNIFORM AND COME
BY MY HOUSE AROUND 7:00.
- NO WAY TO MISINTERPRET THAT.
narrator:
EXCEPT THE ONE.
[country music]
narrator: AND A TRAUMATIZED
STEVE HOLT NEEDS A FATHER.
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
- I KNOW THE FEELING.
I HAD YOU.
I'M YOUR FATHER,
STEVE HOLT.
I CAN'T HIDE FROM IT
ANYMORE.
- I WON'T FORGET THIS, DAD.
[door closes]
- I WILL.
I WILL.