narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL WAS HEADING TO WORK
WHEN HE SAW SOMETHING HE HAD
NEVER SEEN BEFORE LUNCH--
HIS TWIN SISTER LINDSAY.
- YOU'RE UP?
- YEAH. I WORK
FOR OUR ATTORNEY NOW.
- BOB LOBLAW. OF COURSE.
WHAT IS HE THINKING?
I MEAN, HOW'S IT GOING?
- LOUSY.
YOU KNOW, I ONLY TOOK
THIS NANNY JOB
SO HE'D GIVE ME A FREE DIVORCE
AND THEN MARRY ME
SO I'D NEVER
HAVE TO WORK AGAIN.
BUT ALL HE SEEMS TO CARE ABOUT
IS THAT DAUGHTER OF HIS.
- I GOT MY HORSE TO CANTER
TODAY. FIRST TIME.
- I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO MAKE LOVE ON A HORSE.
- AND TOMORROW, WE'RE GONNA
WORK WITHOUT A LUNGE LINE.
- THAT'S SO FUNNY, BECAUSE
I CAN PUT MY LEG BEHIND MY HEAD.
I MEAN, COME ON,
I'M THE NANNY.
- OF COURSE. WHO WOULDN'T WANNA
SNOG THE NANNY?
- "SNOG." IS THAT ANOTHER
ONE OF YOUR NEW BRITISHISMS?
narrator: IT WAS.
MICHAEL HAD RECENTLY
FALLEN BUM OVER NOGGIN
FOR A BEAUTIFUL ENGLISH WOMAN
CALLED RITA.
- DID I SAY SNOG AGAIN?
BLOODY HELL.
LISTEN, YOU WANNA WIN OVER BOB,
YOU GOTTA WIN OVER THE KID,
AND HERE'S WHAT YOU DO.
YOU FIND SOMETHING
THAT YOU'RE GOOD AT,
AND YOU SHARE IT WITH HER.
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT,
SHARE IT WITH US TOO, HUH?
AND TRY NOT TO ACT SO DESPERATE.
OH, MY GOD.
DID I MISS A CALL?
- THIS IS RITA.
JUST WANTED TO SAY HI.
I'M ON MY WAY TO THE TRAIN
STATION. BYE-BYE.
- SHE'S LEAVING.
I GOTTA GET OVER THERE.
narrator:
MICHAEL RACED TO THE STATION.
- GOD, IS THAT HOW I LOOK?
narrator: WHERE RITA WAS BEING
GIVEN HER TICKET.
- HERE'S YOUR TICKET
AND YOUR INSTRUCTIONS.
CALL ME IF YOU GET IN
OVER YOUR HEAD.
- HEY, HI THERE, RITA.
HEY, MICHAEL.
HI. WHERE ARE YOU GOING,
AND HOW LONG YOU GOING FOR?
YOU'RE RIGHT. YOU-YOU--
DO NOT ANSWER THAT.
YOU KNOW,
I'M NOT GETTING CLINGY.
- WHY ARE YOU BREATHING
LIKE THAT?
- OH, I WASN'T HURRYING
TO COME STOP YOU.
I WAS OUT ON---
FOR MY DAILY, UH--
DO YOU RUN AT ALL?
- OH, YES.
I WAS IN THE OLYMPICS ONCE.
I WON A SILVER MEDAL.
- YOU'RE THAT RITA LEEDS?
OH, MY GOODNESS!
AND A SILVER MEDAL, YES.
YOU CAME IN SECOND.
NOW I'M VERY EMBARRASSED
TO BE OUT OF BREATH
IN FRONT OF YOU.
BUT YOU TAKE MY BREATH AWAY.
- OH, MICHAEL.
YOU'RE SUCH A [bleep].
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS STUNNED.
HE ASSUMED RITA
WAS USING THE WORD [bleep]
IN THE AMERICAN SENSE,
MEANING "WEAK" OR "COWARDLY."
IN FACT, RITA MEANT IT
IN THE BRITISH SENSE,
MEANING "SWEET" OR "GENTLE,"
AS IN "PUSSYCAT."
- THE JERRIES AREN'T SO BAD.
THEY'RE JUST BEING LED
BY A ROTTEN APPLE.
- OH, REGGIE.
FIGHTING FOR YOUR COUNTRY,
YOU'RE SUCH A PUSSY.
- WHEN I MISS YOUR LIPS,
I'LL PUT A [bleep]
IN MY MOUTH AND THINK OF YOU.
narrator: THAT ALSO HAD
A DIFFERENT MEANING OVER THERE.
MICHAEL RETURNED HOME,
HOPING TO TAKE SOLACE
IN HIS SON'S COMPANY.
- THINKING YOU AND I SHOULD
MAYBE GO PLAY A LITTLE CATCH.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE GO FOR A RUN.
DO SOME GUY STUFF.
- BUT WE'RE NOT GOOD
AT THAT STUFF.
- YES, I AM. WE BOTH ARE.
narrator: MICHAEL AND HIS SON
HAD NEVER BEEN
A VERY SUCCESSFUL
ATHLETIC TEAM.
IN FACT, THE ONLY THING
GEORGE MICHAEL REALLY LIKED
WAS HANGING MOTIONLESS
FROM THE MONKEY BARS,
WHICH THE PRESIDENT'S COUNSEL
ON FITNESS RANKS AS
"SLIGHTLY EASIER
THAN THE SLIDE."
- ANYWAY, I WAS JUST THINKING
THAT MAYBE WE SHOULD
EMPHASIZE ATHLETICS
A LITTLE BIT MORE
IN THIS FAMILY.
I'M GONNA START US OFF
WITH A PROTEIN DRINK, OKAY?
STILL DOING THAT, HUH?
WELL, I-I DO THINK
WE SHOULD GO FOR A RUN, HUH?
SOME REAL GUY STUFF.
- I'M SUPPOSED TO GO FABRIC
SHOPPING WITH ANN TODAY.
- I THINK WE CAN GO BUTCHER.
- UH, UH, NO.
WE'RE-WE'RE MAKING A GOWN.
SHE'S GONNA BE IN
A BEAUTY PAGEANT.
- YEAH. WHO'S ANN?
- MY-MY GIRLFRIEND. SHE'S--
YOU'VE MET HER SO MANY TIMES,
MET HER AND MET HER.
- NO, I KNOW WHO ANNABELLE IS.
WHO'S THE ANN THAT'S IN
THE BEAUTY PAGEANT?
- THAT'S HER.
HER NAME ISN'T ANNABELLE.
THAT'S ANN.
- NO, I KNOW THAT HER NAME
IS NOT ANNABELLE. I JUST--
THAT'S HOW I REMEMBER HER NAME.
'CAUSE HER BODY'S KIND OF
SHAPED LIKE A--
SHE'S THE BELLE OF THE BALL.
WHAT IS SHE DOIN'
IN THE BEAUTY PAGEANT?
SHE'S--IS SHE RUNNING
THE LIGHTS OR SOMETHING?
- SHE'S IN IT.
SHE'S A-A CONTESTANT.
IT'S SORT OF LIKE
AN INNER BEAUTY PAGEANT.
- AH! THERE IT IS.
IS IT LIKE A CHRISTIAN THING?
- WELL, IT'S HALF.
IT'S AT THE STATE FAIR,
WHICH THIS YEAR'S GONNA BE
A CHURCH AND STATE FAIR.
narrator: IT SEEMS THE STATE
HAD RUN OUT OF MONEY
AND WAS GOING TO CANCEL
THE FAIR
UNTIL IT WAS RESURRECTED
BY THIS MAN,
WHO AGREED TO COVER
THE FAIR'S COSTS
IF IT INCLUDED
A CHURCH PRESENCE.
- I GOT SOME NEWS FOR YOU.
THERE'S NO SUCH THING AS
AN INNER BEAUTY PAGEANT.
THEY'RE JUST GONNA PICK THE
CHICK WITH THE BEST T AND A.
narrator: AS A CHILD,
MAEBY HAD BEEN ENTERED
INTO A NUMBER
OF PROGRESSIVE PAGEANTS
THAT CLAIMED TO CELEBRATE
BEAUTY IN ALL ITS FORMS.
BUT THE WINNERS STILL TENDED
TO HAVE IT GOING ON
IN THE CONVENTIONAL SENSE.
- REMEMBER HOW BADLY
YOU USED TO WANT TO WIN?
- NO, I REMEMBER HOW BADLY
YOU USED TO WANT ME TO WIN.
- YEAH, WE SHOULD HAVE.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE
THAT HAIR OF YOURS CAME FROM.
- SHAMELESS PLUGS ON PLACENTIA.
LOOKS PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
AND THEY'RE NOT LICENSED,
WHICH MEANS BIG SAVINGS.
[glass shatters]
THAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
A LOT LATELY.
- YOU KNOW WHAT? THIS IS
THE PERFECT THING TO DO.
- NO, MOM, I'M NOT GONNA DO IT.
- NO, NO, NOT YOU.
BOB'S DAUGHTER HOPE.
IF I CAN GET HOPE THIS CROWN,
MAYBE HER FATHER
MIGHT JUST WANNA CROWN ME,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
- I'M GUESSING HAVE SEX,
BUT THAT'S MEETING YOU
MORE THAN HALFWAY.
TOBIAS, WANNA CLEAN UP
THAT MIRROR?
AND THE VASE?
- PERHAPS IF I COULD COACH
A CERTAIN YOUNG LADY
TO VICTORY IN THIS PAGEANT,
I CAN GAIN BACK
THE RESPECT OF MY WIFE.
I'LL SHOW THEM
A LITTLE T AND A.
- YOU CAN'T MAKE ME DO IT, DAD.
- TOBIAS AND ANN.
- MY ANN?
NO, I DON'T--I DON'T THINK
WE NEED ANY HELP.
- OH, GEORGE MICHAEL,
SHE'S A GIRL.
I NEED TO TEACH HER
HOW TO BE A WOMAN.
WITHIN HER LIES A QUEEN.
LET ME OUT THAT QUEEN.
- I THINK YOU JUST DID.
- MICHAEL.
- GOB.
- OH, LET ME GET THAT FOR YOU.
UM--
SO A YOUNG NEIGHBORHOOD TOUGH
BY THE NAME OF STEVE HOLT'S
GONNA BE HERE ANY MINUTE.
- YOUR SON.
- ACCORDING TO HIM.
- AND A DNA TEST.
- I HEARD THE JURY'S
STILL OUT ON SCIENCE.
ANYWAY, HE WANTS
TO GO TO THE FAIR.
BUT I DON'T WANNA
HURT HIS FEELINGS,
SO I NEED YOU TO DO IT.
JUST TELL HIM THAT I'M
OUT OF TOWN ON ONE OF MY TRIPS.
- I'M NOT GONNA LIE TO YOUR SON.
- COME ON.
I LIE TO YOURS ALL THE TIME.
MICHAEL, I'M NOT READY
TO BE A DAD.
PLUS, I'M GONNA BE
VERY BUSY THIS WEEK
BEING A JUDGE
FOR THE PAGEANT.
narrator: GOB HAD BEEN
A PAGEANT JUDGE FOR YEARS.
- YOU CAN'T BELIEVE WHAT
IT DOES FOR YOUR SEX LIFE.
- I DON'T WANNA HEAR IT.
- I DON'T WANNA SAY IT.
FIRST PLACE CHICK IS HOT
BUT HAS AN ATTITUDE.
DOESN'T DATE MAGICIANS.
SECOND PLACE IS
SOMEONE WEIRD USUALLY,
LIKE A CHINESE GIRL
OR A GEOLOGIST.
BUT THIRD PLACE,
ALTHOUGH A LITTLE BIT PLAIN,
HAS SUPER LOW SELF-ESTEEM.
SO I STEP IN AND, UH, LAY HER
CROWN UPON MY SWEET HEAD.
- HAVE I MISSED THIS EUPHEMISM?
[knocking]
- STEVE HOLT!
- I SHOULD GO.
- HE'S HIDING FROM ME,
ISN'T HE?
- YOU KNOW, YOU GOTTA STOP
SAYING YOUR NAME ALL THE TIME.
- IT'S JUST THEY HAVE THIS
FATHER-SON TRIATHLON,
AND I JUST WANTED HIM
TO DO IT WITH ME.
- MMM.
- STUPID, HUH?
- THAT'S A PRETTY TOUGH RACE.
- ONLY FOR A WIMP, A WUSS.
A [bleep].
narrator:
AND STEVE DIDN'T MEAN PUSSYCAT.
- UH, STEVE, HOW'D YOU LIKE
TO DO THAT TRIATHLON WITH ME?
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
- YEAH.
- UNCLE MIKE!
- STEVE HOLT!
narrator: BOTH MEN FELT GOOD
ABOUT THEMSELVES.
- UNCLE MIKE!
- STEVE HOLT!
narrator: BUT GOB DIDN'T SHARE
THEIR ENTHUSIASM.
- SO THIS IS HOW MICHAEL
GETS RID OF MY SON--
BY STEALING HIM.
WELL, I'LL JUST HAVE
TO STEAL SOMETHING OF HIS,
LIKE, SAY, HIS BICYCLE,
AS A PLACEHOLDER.
narrator: MICHAEL WAS TRYING
TO PROVE HIS MANLINESS
WITH STEVE HOLT.
- RITA. HEY, IT'S MICHAEL.
JUST WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW
THAT I'M RUNNING
A TRIATHLON AT THE FAIR,
AND IF YOU'RE BACK IN TOWN--
OH, I CAN'T BELIEVE I CHOSE
THIS MOMENT TO CALL YOU.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
AT THE CHURCH AND STATE FAIR,
MAEBY WAS TRYING TO ENROLL
IN THE PAGEANT...
SORT OF.
- YOUR SITUATION
POSES A PROBLEM.
LET ME TALK TO OUR CHAIRMAN.
- HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
MAEBY?
- IT'S SHIRLEY.
I'M JUST HERE TO PROVE
THAT ALL THESE PAGEANTS
CARE ABOUT IS LOOKS.
JUST WATCH.
SHIRLEY'S INNER BEAUTY WILL
GET TRUMPED BY HER OUTER ICKY.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR NOSE?
- IT'S PART OF THE DISGUISE.
ISN'T IT COOL?
THE SAME ONE NICOLE KIDMAN
WORE IN "THE HOURS."
- IT HAD BEEN PURCHASED FOR HER
AT A CHARITY AUCTION SHE'D
ATTENDED AS A STUDIO EXECUTIVE.
- $10,000.
- BY JAMIE KENNEDY.
- YOU'RE SUCH A DEAR.
BUT I'M NOT PUTTING YOU
IN MY REMAKE
OF "A THOROUGHLY POLITE DUSTUP."
- MISS WOLFBEAK,
ALTHOUGH IT COSTS QUITE A BIT
TO PUT IN A RAMP FOR YOU,
WE GOT APPROVAL.
YOU'RE IN.
narrator: AS MAEBY FOUND HERSELF
STUCK IN A BEAUTY PAGEANT,
LUCILLE WAS MEETING
WITH ATTORNEY BOB LOBLAW
ABOUT GETTING HER SON
OUT OF THE ARMY.
- I MEAN, MY GOD.
HE'S ALREADY LOST A HAND.
IF HE LOSES A LEG,
HOW WILL WE EVER
GET HIM OUT OF THE APARTMENT?
- WELL, THE ARMY DOES HAVE
A "ONE IN, ONE OUT" PROGRAM,
WHERE THE INDUCTEE IS RELIEVED
OF DUTY
ONCE HE ENLISTS
SOMEONE TO TAKE HIS PLACE.
- SO I'M SUPPOSED TO FIND
SOME POOR, INNOCENT SOUL
AND HOOK HIM?
- WELL, THAT'S NOT
GOING TO HELP SIGN ANYONE.
WHERE'S YOUR HAND?
- IT GOT STUCK
IN THE PRIZE HOLE AGAIN.
- I TOLD YOU NOT TO PLAY
THAT STUPID GAME ANYMORE.
- OW. THERE GOES NUMBER THREE.
I WASN'T PLAYING IT.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO GET MY OTHER ONE BACK.
- HI. SORRY, SORRY. I TOTALLY
FORGOT ABOUT THIS MEETING.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- YOUR FATHER'S GOTTEN
A LOT OF BAD PRESS
BECAUSE OF THE ESCAPE ATTEMPTS.
VOLUNTEER FOR SOMETHING.
- I'LL DO ANYTHING TO GET OUT OF
THIS [bleep] APARTMENT.
- YOU'LL DO ANYTHING TO GET OUT
OF [bleep]
IN THIS APARTMENT.
- AH, YOU'RE DRUNK.
- YEAH, MOM, CAN YOU JUST--
AND, DAD-- YOU KNOW, WHY DO WE
EVEN NEED THE SURROGATE?
YOU KNOW, DAD'S IN THE
APARTMENT--
- DON'T COME IN HERE.
DON'T COME IN HERE.
I SAID NOT TO COME IN.
- WOULD YOU GET OUT HERE PLEASE?
- I'M WATCHING THE GAME.
- I SAID NOT TO COME IN!
- I DID NOT SPEND MONEY ON
A SURROGATE SO YOU CAN JUST--
- I LOST HIM.
- I THINK YOU'VE GOT
YOUR HANDS FULL
TRYING TO
MAKE THIS GUY LOOK GOOD.
- WELL, THERE'S A "STARTLED
STRAIGHT" PROGRAM AT THE FAIR,
WHICH INVOLVES YOU SPEAKING
WITH AT-RISK MALE YOUTH,
TO SCARE THEM AWAY
FROM CRIMINAL BEHAVIOR.
- OKAY. I CAN DO THAT.
I'M GONNA NEED SOME BIG,
BLOWN-UP PHOTOS OF YOUR MOTHER.
- I THINK THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT
YOUR TIME IN PRISON, DAD.
- OH. OKAY.
WHY NOT?
I MEAN, UH,
IF I DON'T WIN THIS THING,
I'M GONNA BE BACK THERE ANYWAY.
- "AT RISK MALE YOUTH."
THAT SPELLS "ARMY."
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN BUSTER
DISCOVERED A RECRUITING POOL
THE GOVERNMENT HAD BEEN
FISHING FOR YEARS.
- I MAY HEAD DOWN THERE TOO.
- YEAH, I DON'T KNOW, DAD,
"STARTLED STRAIGHT,"
NOT SO SURE
YOU'RE THE GUY FOR THAT.
BUT I'LL LOOK INTO IT
WHILE I'M DOWN AT THE FAIR
SIGNING UP FOR A TRIATHLON.
- TRIATHLON? DO YOU KNOW HOW
HARD A TRIATHLON IS?
PEOPLE LOSE CONTROL
OF EVERY BODILY FUNCTION.
DIDN'T YOU EVER SEE THAT VIDEO?
IT'S LIKE YOUR MOTHER
ON NEW YEAR'S EVE.
narrator: ACTUALLY, LUCILLE
WENT DOWN FASTER.
- YOU'RE NOT EVEN IN SHAPE.
YOU'RE GONNA FALL APART
IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY.
- YOU'RE KIND OF
SCARING ME, DAD.
- YOU SEE?
PERFECT FOR THIS
"STARTLED STRAIGHT" THING.
narrator:
TOBIAS WAS GETTING ANN READY
FOR THE TALENT PORTION
OF THE PAGEANT.
- I THINK WE NEED SOMETHING
WITH A LITTLE MORE SPECTACLE
IN THE ACT.
SOMETHING THAT WILL MAKE YOU
LOOK SMALL AND PRETTY
IN COMPARISON:
A CAMEL.
- YOU KNOW, SHE HAS
A REALLY LOVELY SINGING VOICE.
- I'LL SING TO THE CAMEL.
- YES. WE CAN GOOGLE
SOME DISCO SONGS
WITH THE WORD "HUMP" IN THEM.
- CUTE.
- NO, THAT SOUNDS A BIT RACY.
- OKAY. HE MAY BE AFRAID OF SEX,
BUT YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO WIN WITHOUT IT.
- NO, I'M NOT AFRAID OF SEX.
- OH, GOOD, HAVE SEX
WITH THIS GIRL RIGHT NOW.
DO IT. GO.
GET IN THERE, HAVE SOME SEX
WITH HER RIGHT NOW.
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
ANN, YOU NEED TO DECIDE WHETHER
YOU WANT A MAN OR A BOY.
I KNOW HOW I'D ANSWER.
- GIVE US SOME ROOM,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
I CAN'T BREATHE.
- OKAY, NOW YOU'RE
UPSETTING THE TALENT. OUT!
- [singing] HOW MUCH CAN YOU DO
narrator: MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
HAD BEGUN TRAINING
FOR THE TRIATHLON
TO KEEP FROM HUMILIATING HIMSELF
IN FRONT OF RITA.
- DON'T ASK, "CAN I?"
ASK, "I CAN!"
YOU CAN CONTROL YOUR BLADDER
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD.
NO BLOOD, NO OIL.
THERE'S NO "I" IN WIN!
- [singing] HOW HARD CAN IT BE
GET THOSE BALLS IN THE AIR
KEEP THOSE BALLS IN THE AIR
narrator: MICHAEL RETURNED
CONFIDENT IN HIS MANLINESS
WHEN HE RAN INTO HIS SON,
WHO WAS QUESTIONING HIS OWN.
- HOW IS THAT PAGEANT GOING?
- IT TURNS OUT ANN DOESN'T
WANT ME AROUND DURING IT.
- REALLY?
- WELL, NOW YOU AND ME
CAN GO TO THAT FAIR TOGETHER
TOMORROW AFTER ALL.
- YEAH?
- YEAH, AND MAYBE DO
SOME MAN STUFF LIKE YOU SAID.
- HEY, ACTUALLY,
I'VE ALREADY SIGNED UP
FOR THE FATHER-SON TRIATHLON.
- OH. OKAY, GREAT. YEAH.
I DID WANNA DO THAT WITH YOU.
- I MEAN, I'VE ALREADY--
I PROMISED STEVE HOLT.
YOU KNOW, HE'S OLDER.
IT'S MORE MANLY.
- YOU DON'T THINK I'M MANLY?
- NO, NO, IT'S JUST, UH--
DARN THAT ANNABELLE!
SHE RUINS EVERYTHING.
narrator: BUT THE NEXT MORNING,
MICHAEL AWOKE
TO DISCOVER EVERY MUSCLE IN HIS
BODY WAS EXACTING REVENGE.
- OIL?
narrator:
AND SO WAS HIS BROTHER GOB.
- HEY, DOES ANYONE KNOW WHY
MY HANDLEBARS ARE IN MY BED?
narrator: THE CHURCH AND STATE
FAIR WAS IN FULL SWING.
[Hope singing, indistinct]
AND LINDSAY WATCHED WITH PRIDE
AS HOPE LOBLAW
DID AN ORIGINAL NUMBER THAT
LINDSAY HERSELF HAD WRITTEN.
- [singing] LOVE STAIN ON YOU
- AND NOW, PLEASE WELCOME
ANNABELLE VEAL
PERFORMING "WE THREE KINGS"
WITH A CAMEL TOE.
[accordion]
[snorting]
- [singing] WE THREE KINGS
narrator: MICHAEL ARRIVED AT THE
FAIR SORE FROM OVERTRAINING.
- CAN'T REALLY GO THAT HIGH.
I'M IN A LOT OF PAIN HERE.
- YEAH, YOU KNOW, I FIGURED
YOU'D BE THAT WAY.
SO, UH, COACH GAVE ME THESE.
THEY'RE, UH, PILLS
FILLED WITH OXYGEN.
- YEAH?
- AND THEY KEEP YOU
FROM BEING INCONTINENT.
HAVE ONE. THEY'RE CALLED
OXY-INCONTINENT.
narrator: STEVE DIDN'T HAVE THAT
QUITE RIGHT.
BUT MICHAEL THOUGHT RITA
MIGHT BE COMING,
AND HE WAS DESPERATE
TO IMPRESS HER.
MEANWHILE, MAEBY WAS TRYING TO
GET KNOCKED OUT OF THE PAGEANT.
- POPE IMPERSONATOR, CHURCH.
HOW HAS GOD
INFLUENCED YOUR LIFE?
- ABOUT JUST AS MUCH AS BIG BIRD
AND THE KEEBLER ELVES.
- WELL, MY FAITH
WOULD HAVE BEEN SHAKEN
IF HE HAD TAKEN MY LEGS TOO.
- UH, GOB BLUTH, STATE.
I WAS BETRAYED
BY MY BROTHER MICHAEL.
WHO'S YOUR FAVORITE
FAMILY MEMBER AND WHY?
- DEFINITELY NOT MY SHALLOW,
MATERIALISTIC MOTHER,
WHO ONLY CARES ABOUT LOOKS.
- I THINK WE ALL FEEL
THAT WAY ABOUT OUR MOTHERS.
AND WE ALL HAVE LEGS.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
GEORGE SR. ARRIVED
AT THE STARTLED STRAIGHT TENT.
- I'LL BE WAITING OUT HERE
WITH MY ENLISTMENT FORMS.
SO GO IN THERE AND SCARE THEM
RIGHT INTO MY OPEN ARM!
narrator: BUT AS IT TURNS OUT,
THE FAIR HAD TWO
STARTLED STRAIGHT TENTS,
AND GEORGE SR. HAD WANDERED
INTO THE CHURCH-SPONSORED ONE.
- YOU WANNA BE SOME
GUY'S GIRLFRIEND?
narrator: INTENDED TO SCARE
GAY YOUNG MEN
INTO A HETEROSEXUAL LIFESTYLE.
- YOU WANNA HAVE SOME GUY
REACH AROUND YOU
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT,
START MESSING WITH YOUR JUNK?
- IS HE UGLY?
- NO, IT'S PITCH-BLACK.
YOU DON'T--YOU DON'T SEE HIM.
IT NEVER STOPS, GUYS,
AND EVERYBODY ACTS LIKE
IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
- IS THERE A COVER CHARGE?
narrator:
AND THE INNER BEAUTY PAGEANT
WAS DOWN TO THE FINAL THREE.
- WILL IT BE
THE BEAUTIFUL HOPE LOBLAW,
THE STALWART ANNABELLE VEAL,
OR THE JUSTIFIABLY BITTER
SHIRLEY WOLFBEAK?
narrator: IT BECAME CLEAR THAT
SHIRLEY WAS GOING TO WIN.
- I'M SORRY.
THIS IS WRONG.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN MAEBY
DISPLAYED SOME REAL
INNER BEAUTY.
[all gasping]
ONE OF THESE GIRLS
DESERVES TO WIN.
- SHE CAN STAND!
- MAEBY?
- THAT'S HOW I KNOW HER.
- LET US PRAY.
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE.
- PRAISE THE LORD!
narrator: AND MICHAEL,
NOW FEELING A LITTLE WOOZY,
ARRIVED TO SEE
THE TRIATHLON COURSE,
WHICH CONSISTED
OF SEVERAL TRICYCLES,
FIVE INFLATABLE POOLS,
- WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
narrator: AND FATHERS AND SONS
BEING MANACLED TOGETHER.
- DON'T LET IT PSYCHE YOU OUT.
DID THAT OXY-INCONTINENT
SET IN YET?
- YOU KNEW THIS IS WHAT
THE RACE WAS?
- KIND OF. I MEAN,
THEY CHANGE IT EVERY YEAR
SO YOU CAN'T
REPLICATE IT ON YOUR LAWN.
- WHY DID YOU LET ME
TRAIN SO HARD?
- I JUST THOUGHT YOU WANTED
TO HANG OUT AND DO GUY STUFF.
- THIS ISN'T GUY STUFF.
- I DON'T KNOW WHY I THOUGHT
THAT YOU'D WANNA DO THIS.
THIS IS STUPID, HUH?
- NO, STEVE, STEVE.
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
- YOU'LL DO IT WITH ME?
- WE'RE CHAINED TOGETHER.
BUT, YOU KNOW, RITA'S NOT
HERE YET, AND WHAT THE HELL.
LET'S GO WIN THIS THING.
- LET'S WIN THIS THING!
- WHAT THE HELL.
- WHAT THE HELL!
- NEVER MIND.
LET'S GO AHEAD AND START UP.
narrator: AND AFTER
THE PAGEANT,
GEORGE MICHAEL
WENT TO CONGRATULATE ANN.
- CONGRATULATIONS ON
COMING IN THIRD.
THAT'S AMAZING.
AND I HEARD YOU'RE THE FIRST
CAMEL ACT
TO EVER CRACK THE TOP 10 TOO,
SO THAT'S, LIKE, A RECORD.
AND I'M A BIT RELIEVED,
BECAUSE, UM, I WAS--
I THOUGHT MAYBE
IF YOU CAME IN FIRST,
YOU WOULD HAVE OUTGROWN ME.
- OUTGROWN YOU.
- MM-HMM.
- THAT IS THE TERM
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR.
narrator:
IT SEEMS GOB WAS RIGHT
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS
TO THIRD PLACE CONTESTANTS.
- I MET A MAN.
narrator:
GEORGE MICHAEL WAS DEVASTATED.
IT SEEMED HE'D LOST
HIS GIRL AND HIS FATHER
BECAUSE HE WASN'T MAN ENOUGH.
AND HE WAS FACED WITH A CHOICE.
MICHAEL AND STEVE HOLT
FINISHED THEIR TRIATHLON
IN FIRST PLACE.
OF COURSE, THEY WERE WAY OLDER.
- BELIEVE IT OR NOT, THAT TOOK
ABOUT EVERYTHING I GOT.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT WAS IN THAT PILL,
BUT I DO NOT FEEL SO GREAT.
- IT'S GONNA GET A LITTLE WORSE
BEFORE IT GETS ANY BETTER.
- REALLY?
- WE WON!
- OKAY.
- HEY, POSSIBLE NEPHEW.
- OH, HEY.
- MICHAEL, YOUR SON'S
SIGNING UP FOR THE ARMY.
- WHAT? YOU SIGNED HIM UP
FOR THE ARMY?
- OH, MY GOD, YOU'RE RIGHT.
IF HE GOES IN, I CAN GET OUT.
I'VE GOTTA GET MY NAME
ON HIS FORM.
- HANG ON! HEY!
I GOTTA GET THERE.
I GOTTA STOP THIS.
HEY, YOU GOTTA DO THIS WITH ME.
COME ON.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
RITA NOTICED MICHAEL.
- WAIT FOR ME.
WAIT FOR ME.
- MICHAEL?
- HEY.
- COULD YOU NOT FINISH?
- NO, NO. FIRST PLACE.
FIRST PLACE, I SWEAR.
BUT I'M SORRY,
I GOTTA GO DO SOMETHING.
WAIT, I'M DIZZY.
- UNCLE MIKE, COME ON.
I'LL-I'LL-I'LL TAKE YOU.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
STEVE, STEVE, STEVE--
- LET'S GO. COME ON.
COME ON.
narrator:
AND MEANWHILE, GEORGE SR.
HADN'T SUCCEEDED IN
STARTLING ANYONE BUT HIMSELF.
- I MEAN, THERE'S NOTHING
TO DO ALL DAY
EXCEPT LIFT WEIGHTS
AND FOLD LAUNDRY,
GET THROWN INTO A CAGE
WITH A BUNCH OF SWEATY MEN.
EXCUSE ME.
I CAN'T GO BACK.
- I'M GLAD HE WON'T BE THERE.
- HE'S UGLY.
narrator: GEORGE SR. CAME ACROSS
A U.S. ARMY COMBAT HUMVEE
AND THE POPE MOBILE,
AND HE DECIDED TO ESCAPE
IN THE BULLETPROOF ONE.
- COME ON.
I CAN'T GO BACK!
narrator: AND MICHAEL
CAUGHT UP WITH GEORGE MICHAEL,
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
narrator: WHO WAS THREE RUNGS
AWAY FROM BEING IN THE ARMY.
- I'M BECOMING A MAN, DAD.
ISN'T THAT WHAT EVERYBODY WANTS?
- OF COURSE NOT.
GOB, CAN YOU GET US
OUT OF THESE CHAINS, PLEASE?
- OH, SO YOU STEAL MY SON, AND
NOW YOU NEED ME TO SAVE YOURS.
ALL RIGHT, ONE KEY COMING UP.
[fakes vomiting]
- HE'S A MAGICIAN.
- YEAH. WE-WE NEED YOU
TO SIGN THIS FORM.
- NO, IT'S GOOD, DAD.
THERE'S ALL SORTS OF BENEFITS,
AND IT'S LIKE A FAMILY.
BUT IT'S ALSO AN ARMY OF ONE,
AND IT'S NO PLACE
FOR WIMPS.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU HAVE A FAMILY, OKAY?
AND I'M THE WIMP, NOT YOU.
BECAUSE I COULD NOT TAKE
YOU BEING AWAY IN THE ARMY,
ALL RIGHT?
I LOVE YOU.
[fakes vomiting]
- THAT DID IT.
- HE'S NOT SIGNING UP.
- THAT'S TOO BAD.
I WAS THIS CLOSE TO GETTIN' OUT.
- HEY, I THINK I'M GONNA GO GET
ONE OF THOSE CORN DOG CROSSES.
- WITH ALL THE "CRUCIFIXINS"?
ALL RIGHT.
- THANKS, DAD.
- WAS THAT YOUR SON?
- YES, RITA.
YEAH. THE MOST IMPORTANT PERSON
IN THE WORLD TO ME.
- YOU REALLY ARE QUITE A MAN,
MICHAEL.
- DO YOU REALLY THINK SO?
- OH, YES.
YOU'RE A COMPLETE
AND UTTER [bleep].
narrator: I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE HAD TO BLEEP THAT.
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
SUCH A NICE MOMENT.
ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
BUSTER SIGNS STEVE HOLT UP
FOR THE ARMY.
- NO, NO, YOU CAN'T. YOU CAN'T.
I'M FINALLY READY
TO BE A FATHER TO YOU.
I KNOW THAT NOW.
- I DON'T GO IN
FOR ANOTHER TWO YEARS.
- WELL, AS YOUR FATHER,
CAN I SIGN SOMETHING?
narrator:
AND GEORGE SR. FINDS OUT
THAT A FAKE POPE MOBILE...
- I'LL SEE YOU IN HELL!
[gunfire]
narrator:
CAN'T STOP REAL BULLETS.
- THANK GOD I WASN'T
IN THE HUMVEE.
- [singing] HOW MUCH CAN YOU DO
JUST GRAB AHOLD AND JUGGLE
ALL THOSE BALLS IN THE AIR
HOW HARD CAN IT BE
WITH THOSE BALLS IN THE AIR
KEEP THOSE BALLS IN THE AIR
BALLS IN THE AIR