[narrator
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
[narrator]
MICHAEL HAD SNUCK OUT OF WORK
TO SEE A BRITISH FILM...
WITH HIS BRITISH GIRLFRIEND,
RITA.
- I HATE IT WHEN THEY HIRE
YANKS TO PLAY BRITS.
YOU CAN ALWAYS TELL.
[narrator]
WHEN THEY CAME UPON A TOY STORE.
- WE SHOULD GET GEORGE MICHAEL
ONE OF THESE.
- OH, NO, THAT-THAT-THAT'S
NOT REALLY HIM.
BESIDES, I ALREADY GOT HIM HIS
BIG PRESENT FOR HIS BIRTHDAY.
- A SUIT!
DAD, IT'S A JACK WELCH.
- I WANT YOU TO LOOK
UNDER THE PANTS.
- QUICKEN! PREMIER.
DAD, I HOPE YOU
KEPT THE RECEIPT.
- YOU WANNA RETURN THAT?
- NO, I WANNA DEDUCT IT.
- COME ON, LET'S GET HIM
THE TRAIN.
- IT'S-- REALLY, HE WOULD
ONLY LIKE IT FOR THE RECEIPT.
AND THIS IS CRAZY.
I-I-I, REALLY--
I CAN'T BE
SEEING MOVIES IN THE AFTERNOON,
THEN GOING TO TOY STORES.
I-I HAVE TO WORK.
I'M NOT
EVEN SUPPOSED TO BE HERE.
[narrator]
MICHAEL COULDN'T
TEAR HIMSELF AWAY.
COULD YOU?
- I CAN'T PROMISE IT'LL BE FUN.
[Rita squealing]
[Michael grunting]
OKAY, THAT'S, UH,
THAT WA-- THAT WAS FUN.
STILL, THE LAND PROBABLY
SHOULDN'T HAVE GIVEN OUT
BENEATH US.
BUT WE GOT A MOLE PROBLEM.
- A MOLE PROBLEM?
- YEAH, THEY'VE UNDERMINED
THIS WHOLE HILL.
WE WON'T BE ABLE TO BUILD
ON IT FOR A FEW MONTHS.
BUT IT'S MY FAULT.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHY I SHOULD
HAVE BEEN COMING TO WORK.
THE JAPANESE BACKERS,
IF THEY FIND OUT ABOUT THIS--
THAT WE HAVEN'T
STARTED BUILDING,
THEY MIGHT NOT COME THROUGH
WITH THEIR INVESTMENTS.
- I WON'T TATTLE.
I REALLY FANCY YOU.
- I FANCY YOU TOO.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS FALLING FOR RITA.
- [laughing]
WHEE!
[narrator]
AND RITA WAS FALLING FOR
MICHAEL TOO.
BUT THAT WASN'T
PART OF THE PLAN.
- RITA, YOU'VE DIRT
ON YOUR FACE.
- IT'S FROM SCHOOL.
- I CALLED THE SCHOOL,
AND YOU WEREN'T THERE.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE HERE TO LEARN
THINGS, NOT FALL IN LOVE.
- SO WHAT IF I HAVE?
I'VE GOT FEELINGS, ALL RIGHT?
I'M A WOMAN TOO!
NOT SOME ROBOT YOU GET
TO TELL EVERYTHING TO.
I'M SICK OF IT!
I'M SICK OF IT ALL!
YOUR INSTRUCTIONS
AND YOUR LETTERS!
AND YOUR LITTLE MISSIONS.
AND YOUR STUPID ASSIGNMENTS.
"YOU DO THE MATH, RITA."
WELL, NO, YOU DO THE MATH.
[softly]
OH, GOD.
- DO YOU REMEMBER THIS?
AND THE PLEDGE THAT YOU MADE
WHEN YOU WERE PROMISED IT?
- I SAID I'D DO ANYTHING FOR IT.
- I WANT HIM OUT OF THE PICTURE.
CAN YOU DO THAT?
- I'M A BIG GIRL.
[screams, laughs]
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL RETURNED
HOME AS WELL.
- HEY, WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
- [chuckles] OH,
I GOT HIGHLIGHTS.
IT'LL BLEND IN ABOUT A WEEK.
- HERE. YEAH, I ACTUALLY
MEANT THE COLLAPSE.
- IT PROBABLY HAS SOMETHING TO
DO WITH THE 4,000 HAIR PLUGS
I HAD IN ONE SITTING.
- WELL, MAYBE YOU OUGHTA
SEE A DOCTOR.
- YEAH, BUT HE'S TOO BUSY
GOING TO THE GYM TO SEE
HIS FRIEND FRANK.
- OH, WE'RE MORE THAN FRIENDS.
I'M KIND OF HIS SPOTTER.
MISSED A SPOT.
ANYWAY, WE SHOULD BE
LOOKING AT SOME BIG YEN
COMING IN FROM THE JAPANESE.
AND WHEN IT DOES,
I'M TAKING MY GYM BUDDY
OUT TO DINNER.
[laughs]
I BARELY EVEN KNOW YOU.
WHO'S FRANK?
- I'VE BEEN WANTING TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT THAT,
BUT IT'S A LITTLE AWKWARD.
- OH, WELL.
[chuckles]
I'VE BEEN WANTING TO HAVE
MY OWN AWKWARD TALK AS WELL.
- I THINK WE CAN BE MORE
THAN JUST GYM BUDDIES.
- YOU'RE BLOWING MY MIND, FRANK.
- I'M AN AGENT, AND I'D LIKE
TO WORK WITH YOU.
- OH. OH!
[chuckles]
WELL, THAT IS GREAT NEWS.
OKAY, GOOD.
I'M SO GLAD YOU WENT FIRST.
UH, UH WHAT AGENCY ARE YOU WITH?
[narrator]
FRANK SAID C.I.A.,
A GOVERNMET AGENCY THAT WAS
RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS CATASTROPHE.
BUT TOBIAS THOUGHT HE SAID
C.A.A., A TALENT AGENCY THAT WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS ONE.
- FRANK'S IN THE BUSINESS,
MICHAEL.
HE'S GOT A BIG
PROJECT FOR ME.
SAYS IT'S "TOP SECRET."
HE KIND OF LOOKS LIKE YOU.
SAME SIZE.
SAME CURLY HAIR.
- TOBIAS, MAYBE
YOU SHOULD SPEND LESS TIME...
FOCUSED ON YOUR LOOKS,
AND MORE TIME FOCUSED ON
YOUR DAUGHTER, OKAY?
HER GRADES ARE TERRIBLE.
SHE'S GONNA START GETTING F's.
[narrator]
ACTUALLY, SHE'D
ALREADY GOTTEN ONE,
AS THE MOVIE SHE'D RELEASED
IN HER SECRET LIFE AS A STUDIO
EXECUTIVE WAS LOSING MONEY.
BUT MAEBY HAD A WAY TO FIX THAT.
- WE TURN IT INTO A RIDE.
- A RIDE?
- ON THE STUDIO TOUR.
WHAT USED TO BE
THE HELL TUNNEL...
NOW BECOMES THE TUNNEL
OF LOVE, INDUBITABLY.
- BUT DIDN'T SOME PEOPLE
DIE IN HELL TUNNEL?
- THAT IS AN URBAN LEGEND.
TWO ELDERLY PEOPLE
GOT BADLY SCALDED...
WHEN THEY TRIED TO CLIMB
INTO THE LAVA CAULDRON,
BUT I'VE GOT THAT COVERED.
- JUST LIKE THE POSTER!
- GRADES LIKE THOSE, SHE'S
GONNA BE TAKING TICKETS
AT A MOVIE THEATER
THE REST OF HER LIFE.
- YOU KNOW WHAT, YOU'RE
ONE TO TALK.
YOU'VE COMPLETELY
IGNORED THIS FAMILY...
SINCE THAT BRITISH BIRD
FLEW INTO YOUR LIFE.
- NO, I HAVEN'T.
WELL, MAYBE A LITTLE.
BUT, YOU KNOW, SHE'S AMAZING.
YOU KNOW, SHE WAS
IN THE OLYMPICS?
[narrator]
SHE WASN'T.
- SHE'S THAT RITA LEEDS?
- MM-HMM.
- WASN'T SHE ON
THE COVER OF NEWSWEEK?
[narrator]
NO.
- YES.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS THINKING
OF THIS MAN.
- SHE EVEN PLAYS THE BANJO.
ALTHOUGH, I DO HAVE TO SPEND
MORE TIME AT WORK.
I WAS AT THE PROPERTY
THE JAPANESE FUNDED TODAY.
THE WHOLE BACKSIDE HAS MOLES.
- THAT'S FRANK'S PROBLEM TOO.
[narrator]
LATER THAT DAY,
MICHAEL WENT INTO THE OFFICE
TO FIND THE REST OF HIS FAMILY.
- WELL, LOOK WHO'S FINALLY
GRACING US WITH HIS PRESENCE.
- WHAT'S THE SURROGATE
DOING HERE?
- WE'RE MEETING
WITH THE LAWYERS.
- SO I'VE HIRED THIS GUY
TO BE MY EYES AND EARS.
- YOU KNOW, DAD, THIS GUY
COSTS US A FORTUNE.
- HE'S WORTH EVERY PENNY.
- HEY, I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
- OH, MICHAEL.
- MR. LOBLAW.
- I'LL CATCH YOU UP.
THE JAPANESE ARE COMING.
- THEY ARE?
- SOMEBODY TIPPED THEM OFF
THAT THE PROPERTY WASN'T
READY FOR BUILDING.
- WHICH IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
IF MICHAEL HADN'T BEEN SO BUSY
WITH HIS ENGLISH MUFFIN.
- TYPICAL.
- DELICIOUS.
- I NEED A DRINK.
- I'LL TAKE AN ENGLISH MUFFIN.
- WE'LL HAVE TO BE HONEST
WITH THESE JAPANESE INVESTORS.
THEY, UH, COME FROM A CULTURE
THAT VALUES HONOR AND RESPECT.
- AND GODZILLA!
[roaring]
- GODZIRRA!
- JUST SIT DOWN.
OKAY, GUYS.
- GODZIRRA!
[roaring]
- [roaring]
- THIS NEEDS TO STOP NOW!
OKAY, THIS IS EXACTLY
WHAT WE SHOULDN'T DO
WHEN THEY SHOW UP.
- [roaring]
- MOM! THAT'S ENOUGH.
- WHAT?
WE'RE OUT OF VODKA.
- SORRY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
DOING GODZILLA.
- [shrieking like Godzilla]
- MOM, THAT'S ENOUGH.
- WHAT? I'M LAUGHING.
- OH.
- HEY, MAYBE THAT'S IT.
MAYBE WE SHOULD DO
TO THE JAPANESE WHAT
THEY DO IN THEIR MOVIES.
BUILD A MINIATURE CITY.
PUT IT OUTSIDE THE WINDOW.
TELL THEM IT'S FAR AWAY.
IT'LL LOOK REAL IF YOU SQUINT.
GOD KNOWS THEY'RE SQUINTERS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, DAD?
A WHOLE... "TINY TOWN."
[music box]
- ANOTHER BRILLIANT
IDEA, EINSTEIN.
- REALLY?
YOU LIKE TO BUILD IT WITH ME?
- LARRY REALLY NEVER KNOWS
HOW TO SELL THE SARCASM.
- IT'S A STUPID IDEA.
- UH. I'LL BUILD IT
WITH YOU, GOB.
- OH, GREAT, THAT'S ANOTHER
BRILLIANT IDEA, STEINBERG.
- I AGREE WITH MICHAEL.
IF YOU TAKE MONEY FROM THESE
PEOPLE UNDER FALSE PRETENSES,
YOU'LL BE COMMITTING FRAUD.
THE GOVERNMENT'S ALREADY
WATCHING YOUR FATHER CLOSELY.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH HIS MAIL.
THEY WANT TO PUT YOUR FATHER
IN PRISON FOR GOOD.
- YEAH, BOB'S RIGHT.
WE'VE GOT TO START
THINKING PRACTICALLY.
LIFE IS NOT SOME
CHEESY JAPANESE MOVIE...
WHERE THE HERO PULLS ON
A PAIR OF JET PANTS AND--
- FLIES OFF THE BALCONY
LIKE ASTROBOY.
[narrator]
AND THAT'S WHEN GEORGE SR.
DID A WEB SEARCH FOR
THE WORDS, "JET PANTS."
- EVEN BETTER.
- THE BIGGER PROBLEM IS,
WHO ALERTED THE JAPANESE?
I THINK YOU MIGHT HAVE A SPY.
THIS ROOM, OR SOMEONE IN IT,
MIGHT EVEN BE WIRED
WITH A LISTENING DEVICE.
YOU NEED TO FIND
THAT LEAK AND PLUG IT.
YOUR FATHER SAID THAT HE WAS
SET UP BY A BRITISH SYNDICATE.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD LOOK
FOR SOMEBODY ENGLISH.
- [woman singing]
FOR BRITISH EYES ONLY
- WHAT?
- I THINK MICHAEL'S
ALREADY PLUGGED OUR LEAK.
- WHAT IS THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- YOU'VE BEEN SPENDING
A LOT OF TIME WITH RITA.
AND SHE'S "BRITISHISH."
- SHE'S A SPY.
- I HAVEN'T TOLD RITA ANYTHING.
[narrator]
THIS WAS NOT STRICTLY TRUE.
LET'S START WITH
MY FAMILY'S MISDEMEANORS,
AND THEN PUSH
RIGHT ON THROUGH TO
THE LIGHTER TREASONS.
THE JAPANESE BACKERS--
IF THEY FIND OUT THAT
WE HAVEN'T STARTED BUILDING,
THEY MIGHT NOT COME THROUGH
WITH THEIR INVESTMENTS.
THEN HE SIPHONED OFF
THE ENTIRE PENSION FUND
INTO A DUMMY CORPORATION,
FILED FOR BANKRUPTCY,
AND USED-- DO YOU KNOW
ANY OTHER SONGS?
- SHE'S A SPY!
- RITA IS NOT A SPY, OKAY?
SHE'S A BEAUTIFUL,
ELEGANT WOMAN.
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
- WHAT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE
IS WHY SHE'S DATING YOU.
- NO, THAT'S A GOOD POINT.
ACTUALLY, MY SOURCES
TELL ME THAT THE LEAK
GOES BY THE NAME "MR. F."
- [woman singing]
MR. F
- AH, MR. F.
RITA'S NOT A MAN.
- AS FAR AS YOU KNOW.
- AND IT COULD BE AN ALIAS.
- ALIAS IS A SHOW ABOUT A SPY!
- ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT!
I FINALLY FIND SOMEONE THAT
I REALLY CARE ABOUT, MY FAMILY
TRIES TO DRIVE US APART.
IT'S NOT GONNA WORK.
SO YOU KNOW WHAT?
I GOT A SWITCH FOR YOU.
YOU GUYS HANDLE THIS PROBLEM.
I AM GONNA GO HAVE SOME FUN.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
DESERTING THE FAMILY
WHEN WE MOST NEED HIM.
SHAMEFUL.
- GOB, I'M SENDING YOU
A PACKAGE.
YOU'LL KNOW WHAT TO DO WITH I.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS UPSET,
AND HE CALLED RITA.
- HELLO?
- HEY,
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
I'M GOING TO START
WORKING LESS, AND I DO WANT
TO START HAVING MORE FUN.
SO, I'D LIKE TO
TAKE YOU OUT TOMORROW.
ALL DAY, ANYWHERE YOU WANT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
[TV announcer]
HELL TUNNEL TAKES ANOTHER NAME.
WILL IT TAKE ANOTHER LIFE?
- OH, I SAY YES.
ONLY, I'M GOING
TO TAKE YOU OUT.
[woman singing]
MR. F
[narrator]
THE NEXT MORNING,
MICHAEL WAS HEADING OUT
FOR HIS DAY WITH RITA.
- GEORGE MICHAEL.
- HEY, I LOVE MY PRESENT, DAD.
I'D WEAR IT TO SCHOOL, BUT
WHO NEEDS A WELCH WEDGE, RIGHT?
- [chuckles]
YEAH.
- THAT'S WHEN THEY--
- ENOUGH BUSINESS. IN FACT,
I GOT YOU ANOTHER PRESENT.
IT'S SOMETHING I SAW YESTERDAY
WHEN I WAS OUT WITH RITA.
IT'S TIME FOR US
TO START HAVING SOME FUN.
- I DON'T KNOW.
"FUN" AND "FAILURE"
BOTH START OUT THE SAME WAY.
- LET'S JUST GO AHEAD
AND RIP THIS DOWN, HUH?
[narrator]
AND LARRY, THE SURROGATE,
SHOWED UP TO PICK UP
THE JET PACK THAT GEORGE SR.
HAD SENT TO THE MODEL HOME.
- WHAT IS THAT, A TRAIN SET?
LOOK DOWN, LARRY.
- NO, NOT DOWN AT YOUR FEET.
- LEFT.
MY LEFT, YOUR RIGHT.
- WHAT IS THE MATTER
WITH THIS GUY?
AND, LET ME GUESS,
HE'S PROBABLY--
- SAYING ALL THAT TOO.
- IT IS A TRAIN SET!
THOSE JAPANESE SITES.
I'M NEVER GONNA FIND MY WAY--
- PAST THAT HALLWAY SENSOR.
- DAD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
IS THIS THE PACKAGE YOU SENT ME?
TINY TOWN.
THIS IS FOR
TINY TOWN, ISN'T IT?
YOU DID LIKE MY IDEA,
DIDN'T YOU, DAD?
- I THINK HE'S IN THE CAN.
[narrator]
ACTUALLY, GEORGE SR.
WAS IN THE KITCHEN,
TRYING TO SOOTHE HIMSELF
WITH AN ICE CREAM SANDWICH.
AND THAT'S WHEN HE DISCOVERED
A WAY TO POSSIBLY SLIP BY
THE SENSORS.
- IF MOTHER SEES THIS,
SHE WILL BLOW A COW.
[groaning]
- UH-OH.
- DAD?
OH, COOL, A TRAIN SET.
- OH, I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
ONE OF THOSE.
- MAYBE WE COULD BUILD
OUR TINY TOWN TOGETHER.
DO YOU WANT TO, DAD?
[narrator]
BUSTER HAD ALWAYS WANTED
TO DO THE SAME WITH GOB.
- GOODY! YEAH.
I DO WANT TO.
- YEA.
I DO WANT TO. GOODY.
[narrator]
GOB WAS THRILLED, AS WAS BUSTER.
ONLY LARRY WAS DISAPPOINTED.
BUT HE WAS SUCH A PRO
YOU'D NEVER KNOW IT.
AND BACK AT THE GYM, TOBIAS WAS
FINDING OUT MORE ABOUT THE
PROJECT THE AGENT HAD SUGGESTED.
- COME ON!
WHAT ARE
YOU GONNA TELL ME?
WHAT'VE YOU GOT FOR ME?
- THE JAPANESE INVESTORS
YOU TOLD US ABOUT ARE GOING
OVER TO YOUR PLACE TODAY.
I NEED YOU THERE WHEN THEY ARE.
WE NEED YOU TO BE A MOLE.
- OH.
KIND OF A BACKER'S AUDITION.
OKAY, I GET IT.
ALL RIGHT. WELL THEN, FRANK,
I SHALL BE A BIGGER,
HAIRIER MOLE THAN THE ONE
ON YOUR INNER LEFT THIGH.
[laughing]
[narrator]
AND LATER,
MICHAEL AND RITA WERE ON
THE TANTAMOUNT STUDIOS TOUR.
- THE THING SHE DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND ABOUT
BOVINE
SPONGIFORM ENCEPHALITIS IS--
- HOLD! HOLD!
THE TRAM.
LET'S GET OUT
OF HERE, FOLKS! MAKE SOME ROOM!
MAKE SOME ROOM!
- LOOK! IT'S MALCOLM
IN THE MIDDLE!
- IN THE MIDDLE OF SHOOTING,
I GUESS.
- OH, THAT'S OKAY.
IT'S MORE IMPORTANT TO SHOW
HOW WE MAKE THE SHOW
THAN ACTUALLY MAKE IT.
[bleep] TANTAMOUNT.
[ringing]
- HELLO?
- THEY DROPPED
OFF THE PACKAGE YOU SENT,
BUT I DON'T THINK
I'M OLD ENOUGH FOR IT.
- OF COURSE YOU ARE.
I WANT YOU TO HAVE A LITTLE FUN.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BREAK ANYTHING.
[narrator]
BUT OF COURSE,
MICHAEL THOUGHT HE WAS
TALKING ABOUT THE TRAIN SET.
NOT THE EXTREMELY
DANGEROUS JET PACK THE BOY HAD
JUST FOUND AT THE FRONT DOOR.
- WELL, WHAT IF I CRASH IT?
- THAT'S HALF THE FUN.
[narrator]
AND SOON THE TOUR ARRIVED AT
THE TUNNEL OF LOVE, INDUBITABLY.
[Woman On P.A.]
SO TAKE THE HAND
OF SOMEONE YOU LOVE...
AS WE ENTER THE TUNNEL
OF LOVE, INDUBITABLY.
[Man on P.A.]
NO, LOVE HELL.
[laughing]
[narrator]
BUT MICHAEL WAS HAPPY TO HOLD
THE HAND OF SOMEONE HE DID LO.
AND THEN,
HE NOTICED HER BRACELET.
[narrator]
MICHAEL HAD
JUST NOTICED THAT RITA WAS
WEARING A SUSPICIOUS BRACELET.
- WHAT DOES YOUR BRACELET SAY?
- [chuckling]
NOTHING.
OH, LOOK. LOOK, THERE THEY ARE
ON THE BICYCLE MADE FOR TWO.
- IT SAYS MR. F, DOESN'T IT?
WHO IS HE?
- NOBODY.
I CAN'T TELL YOU!
OH, GOD.
HE FOLLOWED US.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU KNOW THAT MAN?
- IT'S NOT WHAT YOU THINK IT IS.
IT'S MY UNCLE.
- IS THAT MR. F?
WHAT DOES HE WANT?
- HE WANTS YOU
OUT OF THE PICTURE.
- BLOODY RIGHT I DO.
- H-HEY!
- OH!
- YOU LIED TO ME, RITA!
YOU MADE ME TURN
AGAINST MY FAMILY.
BUT IT'S OVER NOW.
[buzzer sounding]
- OH! ME-- [bleep] ARE WET.
- [whimpers]
[narrator]
AND MAEBY RECEIVED
A CALL ABOUT THE LATEST
LAVA CAULDRON ACCIDENT.
- ALREADY?
IT'S ONLY BEEN AN HOUR.
I'M GONNA LOSE THIS JOB.
MAYBE I SHOULD LET MORT
TAKE ME OUT TO DINNER.
- MAEBY?
- OKAY, I'M DEFINITELY
GONNA LOSE THIS JOB.
I CAN EXPLAIN.
- RITA SET ME UP.
SHE SET US ALL UP.
THIS BEAUTIFUL, FUNNY,
BRILLIANT WOMAN WAS A SPY.
EVERYBODY WAS RIGHT.
IT WAS TOO GOOD TO BE TRUE.
AND I... AM TURNING HER IN.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING ELSE.
I WOULD NOT WANT TO BE THE NEXT
WOMAN WHO TRIES TO FOOL ME.
- WELL, THAT WAS A FREEBIE.
[chuckles]
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL,
MEANWHILE, WAS TRYING TO
SOLVE A MYSTERY OF HIS OWN.
[speaking Japanese]
THE JET PACK...
HAD COME WITH AN INSTRUCTIONAL
DVD THAT SEEMED TO CONFUSE
MORE THAN CLARIFY.
WHAT WAS CLEAR
WAS THAT THE GIFT WAS
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
[cartoon robot, woman
both speaking Japanese ]
AND IT DID SEEM
LIKE A LOT OF WORK...
FOR A LITTLE PAYOFF.
- HAVE FUN!
HAVE FUN.
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, GOB WAS BONDING
WITH THE MAN HE THOUGHT
HIS FATHER WAS CONTROLLING.
- ALMOST DONE
WITH THE WATER TOWER.
- NEAT-O.
[narrator]
HIS REAL FATHER, HOWEVER, HAD
GOTTEN LOST WITHIN THE WALLS.
- WHERE THE HELL AM I?
[narrator]
HE WAS ACTUALLY SOMEWHERE
BETWEEN THE LINEN CLOSET
AND THE GUEST ROOM.
- I'M REALLY GLAD THAT
WE'RE DOING THIS TOGETHER.
[chuckles]
I'VE NEVER FELT
SO CLOSE TO YOU.
- OH!
I FEEL THE SAME WAY.
- HE'S CRYING NOW.
- OH, GOD, LOOK AT US.
WE'RE LIKE A COUPLE OF GIRLS
ON THE LAST DAY OF CAMP.
[narrator]
RIGHT OUTSIDE THE HOUSE,
TOBIAS WAS WORKING WITH THE MAN
HE THOUGHT WAS A TALENT AGENT.
- YOU READY?
- OH, YES.
I'M GONNA BE A GREAT MOLE.
[chuckling]
CHECK, TWO, THREE.
"LET LILLY LICK
LIONEL'S LUSTY LEATHERS.
LET LILLY LICK LIONEL'S--"
- THE LEVELS ARE FINE.
- ALL RIGHT.
- REMEMBER, NO ONE
CAN KNOW IT'S YOU.
WE NEED TO CAPTURE GEORGE SR.
- CAPTURE GEORGE SR.?
WHAT-- IS THAT WHAT
YOU HIRED ME TO DO?
- YOU DIDN'T REALIZE THAT?
- NO. BUT IT DOES
MAKE PERFECT SENSE.
I HAVE PLAYED HIM BEFORE.
[narrator]
HE HAD, IN THE POORLY NARRATED
REALITY SERIES, SCANDALMAKERS.
- IT'S GONNA BE TOUGH TO WORK
THAT INTO THE CHARACTER,
AND IT'S GOING TO FIGHT
THE COSTUME I RENTED,
BUT I DIDN'T TAKE SIX WEEKS
OF IMPROV CLASSES AT
THE GROUNDLINGS FOR NOTHING.
[chuckling]
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS ON THE PHONE
TO BOB LOBLAW.
- I DON'T EVEN THINK
SHE'S HERE LEGALLY,
ALL RIGHT?
SHE'S TAKEN ADVANTAGE
OF ME.
I-I WANT YOU TO
TAKE CARE OF THIS.
CALL THE C.I.A.,
DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO DO.
- FINE, BUT YOU TAKE CARE
OF YOUR FAMILY.
I THINK THEY'RE
GOING AHEAD WITH THIS HOAX.
AND IF MONEY CHANGES HANDS,
YOU'RE ALL GOING TO JAIL.
- WELL, UNFORTUNATELY THE ROADS
ARE OUT, SO WE CAN'T TAKE YOU
UP THERE TO SEE IT IN PERSON,
BUT IF YOU STAND ABSOLUTELY
STILL RIGHT THERE,
AND JUST SQUINT
IN-INTO THE LIGHT,
AND BEHOLD, SUDDEN HILL!
- GOB!
DON'T!
[narrator]
IT ACTUALLY LOOKED PRETTY GOOD.
EVEN THE FINANCIERS THOUGHT SO.
ISHIRO SAID,
"I AM REASSURED. AND THEY TREAT
US WITH RESPECT THIS TIME."
MOTOYOSHI SAID,
"I THOUGHT THE WOMAN WAS
PRETENDING AS A MONSTER,
BUT SHE WAS
JUST OUT OF VODKA."
- LET'S GO AHEAD AND CLOSE
THE CURTAINS, AND NOT ACCEPT
ANY MONEY WHILE WE'RE AHEAD.
- SO, AS YOU CAN SEE,
ANY RUMOR OF A MOLE PROBLEM
IS COMPLETELY UNTRUE.
[narrator]
BUT, UNFORTUNATELY,
THIS WAS JUST AS TOBIAS APPEARED
IN HIS RENTED MOLE OUTFIT.
- [Tobias] I'M A MOLE!
- NOT THE VILLAGE!
- FAMILIES CAN COME-- OW! OW!
I'M VERY PARTICULAR
ABOUT BUILDING CODES.
- THE WATER TOWER.
- AND THIS WATER TOWER
DOES NOT PASS MUSTER.
LUCILLE!
- WHO CAN SAVE OUR VILLAGE?
[narrator]
AS IT TURNED OUT,
IT WAS GEORGE MICHAEL...
WHO HAD FINALLY
GOTTEN HIS GRANDFATHER'S
JET PACK TO WORK.
- [laughing]
- [grunting]
- HARD TO BREATHE IN THIS THING.
IT'S REALLY HOT.
I'M SWEATING ALL OVER MYSELF.
- [gasps]
- I CAN'T STOP THIS THING!
- YOU'RE BLOWING MY AUDITION!
[narrator translating]
I ACHE WITH EMBARRASSMENT.
THE JAPANESE WERE NEVER
TO BE HEARD FROM AGAIN.
- OKAY, WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
OKAY, THAT'S NO SURPRISE.
GEORGE MICHAEL?
- DAD, I-I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T FLY IT VERY WELL,
ALL RIGHT?
I THINK I WOULD
RATHER HAVE THE WELCH.
- I DIDN'T BUY YOU THAT.
I BOUGHT YOU THE TRAIN SET,
WHICH YOU GUYS JUST DESTROYED.
- DID YOU KEEP THE RECEIPT?
[feedback squealing]
- WHAT IS THAT?
- IT'S FEEDBACK.
IS SOMEONE ELSE WIRED?
- OH, THAT'S ME.
[chuckles]
MY FRIEND FRANK WIRED ME.
HE WANTED ME TO BE A MOLE.
- OUR COVER'S BLOWN.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
GOOD-BYE, TOBIAS.
- HE WANTED YOU TO BE A MOLE?
[tires screeching]
OH, MY GOD.
TOBIAS FUNKE
YOU'RE MR. F.
WHICH MEANS THAT MAN WAS
RITA'S UNCLE.
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
- I HAVE TO GET THIS SUIT BACK.
- THEY DESTROYED OUR TOWN.
BUT THEY CAN'T
TAKE AWAY OUR MEMORIES.
- OH! I'VE HAD--
- THE TIME OF MY LIFE.
- I THINK HE'S BEING
SARCASTIC, GOB.
- NO, I'M NOT, MOTHER.
[gasps]
I MEAN LOVER.
- I LIKE MAKING LOVE TO MOTHER.
- I MEAN LOVER!
- OH, MY GOD.
BUSTER, IS THAT YOU?
- YES.
GOB, IT'S JUST I WANTED
TO SPEND SOME TIME WITH YOU.
THAT'S ALL.
AND YOU ENJOYED IT.
YOU CAN'T DENY THAT.
- [sighs]
I GUESS YOU'RE RIGHT.
MAYBE WE SHOULD SPEND
MORE TIME TOGETHER.
- OH, I'D REALLY LIKE THAT.
- IT'S WEIRD.
IT TOOK SOME IDIOT PARROT MAN
WITH A CAMERA IN HIS HAT
TO BRING US TOGETHER.
[narrator]
BUT EVEN A PRO LIKE LARRY
HAS A BREAKING POINT.
[knocking]
- RITA.
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I HAVE TO PACK.
- PACK? WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- SOMEONE CALLED
THE BOBBIES ON US.
- NO, NO.
- MY UNCLE AND I HAVE
TO GO BACK TO BIG BRITAIN.
- OH, THAT WAS ME, RITA.
I AM SO, SO SORRY.
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT WAS GOING ON.
WHY DID YOUR UNCLE
THREATEN ME?
- HE THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT BE TROUBLE.
- THAT WAS ACTUALLY
VERY ASTUTE OF HIM.
- GOOD-BYE, MICHAEL.
YOU KNOW,
I REALLY DID FANCY YOU.
I CAN'T STAY HERE NOW.
- MARRY ME.
- WHAT?
- LET ME MARRY YOU.
YOU CAN GET A GREEN CARD,
YOU-YOU CAN STAY AND WE CAN JUST
SEE IF THIS WORKS, YOU KNOW?
IT SOUNDS CRAZY, BUT THIS
WILL GIVE US A CHANCE...
TO GET AWAY FROM
BOTH OF OUR FAMILIES
AND SEE IF THIS WORKS.
MIGHT BE FUN.
- [softly] YES.
- REALLY?
- YES.
YES, YES, YES!
BUT LET'S GO RIGHT NOW, OKAY?
BEFORE MY UNCLE GETS OUT OF THE
SHOWER FOR SOME MORE CIGARETTES.
YOU TAKE THAT,
I GOTTA LEAVE A NOTE.
[narrator]
BUT THERE WAS
ONE PIECE OF INTELLIGENCE
THAT MICHAEL DIDN'T HAVE.
- INTERESTING.
- DON'T EVEN
THINK ABOUT IT, JAY.
SHE'S AN M.R.F.
- M.R.F.? WHAT'S THAT?
- MENTALLY RETARDED FEMALE.
- THAT EXPLAINS WHAT
SHE'S DOING WITH HIM.
- AND THE HATS.
- OH, MY GOD!
SHE'S GONNA MARRY HIM.
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
GEORGE SR., DISORIENTED
IN THE WALLS, ALMOST MAKES
CONTACT WITH A NEW MOLE.
- [screams]
[narrator]
NOT THAT ONE. WAIT FOR IT.
AND MICHAEL AND RITA
START A NEW LIFE TOGETHER.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- A PRIZE.
A LOVELY, LOVELY PRIZE.