narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL WAS SHARING SOME VERY
IMPORTANT NEWS WITH HIS PARENTS.
- I AM GETTING MARRIED.
- WHO THE HELL TO?
- WHO DO YOU THINK?
RITA.
- HER?
- WHY?
- WELL, FIRST, SHE NEEDS A GREEN
CARD TO STAY IN THE COUNTRY.
- THERE IT IS.
- SHE NEEDS A GREEN CARD
TO STAY IN THE COUNTRY...
BECAUSE, SECONDLY, WE'RE REALLY
CRAZY ABOUT EACH OTHER.
- YOU HARDLY KNOW HER.
- I KNOW ALL THE IMPORTANT
STUFF.
SHE WAS IN THE OLYMPICS.
- HUH!
- SHE'S SWEET, SMART,
SHE'S BEAUTIFUL. SHE'S SPECIAL.
narrator: SHE WAS SPECIAL.
- ARE HOUSES HARD TO MAKE?
- ACTUALLY, THE HARDEST PART
IS FINDING THE LAND.
narrator:
BUT SHE WASN'T SMART.
- INSTEAD OF MAKING HOUSES,
MAYBE YOU SHOULD MAKE LAND--
narrator: FOR RITA HAD ONLY
MENTALLY PROGRESSED...
- ON THE OCEAN.
narrator: TO THE LEVEL
OF A FIRST-GRADER.
- THERE'S NO LAND ON THE OCEAN.
narrator: MICHAEL MIGHT HAVE
NOTICED HER DISABILITY...
IF IT HAD NOT BEEN MASKED
BY HER ENGLISH ACCENT.
- YOU'RE BRILLIANT.
narrator: YEAH, SHE WASN'T.
- I KNOW SHE'S A
REALLY, REALLY GOOD PERSON.
AND EVERYTHING ELSE IS GONNA BE
LITTLE SURPRISES ALONG THE WAY.
narrator: WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF THAT ONE BIG ONE.
- THE WEDDING IS IN ONE MONTH.
- OH.
- A MONTH!
- NOW, LOOK.
JUST BECAUSE A WOMAN
GETS PREGNANT,
DOESN'T MEAN
YOU HAVE TO MARRY HER.
TOO MANY LIVES HAVE BEEN RUINED
BECAUSE SOME CHEAP WAITRESS
AT A HOJO...
SAID SHE USED AN I.U.D.
- IT WAS STUCKEY'S.
- BUT I BELIEVED YOU.
- SHE'S NOT PREGNANT.
WE HAVEN'T EVEN
SLEPT TOGETHER.
- [laughing]
- [laughing] THIS IS FUNNY.
- HE'S GAY!
- WHERE'S YOUR HAND?
- I'M HAVING MY HIGH SCHOOL RING
PUT ON IT,
AND MY HOOK IS STUCK
IN THE STAIR CAR.
[radio] DOMO ARIGATO, MR. ROBOTO
- DOMO ARIGATO, MR. ROBOTO
- [singing] DOMO, DOMO
- OH.
- DO YOU THINK GETTING MARRIED
WILL SOLVE YOUR SEX PROBLEM?
- NO, WE DON'T HAVE A PROBLEM.
WE JUST HAVEN'T HAD THE RIGHT
OPPORTUNITY YET.
- LINDSAY SAID RITA SLEPT OVER
LAST NIGHT.
- YES, BUT I GAVE HER THE
BEDROOM
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT HER
TO FEEL PRESSURED.
narrator:
ACTUALLY, IT WAS MICHAEL
WHO FELT A LITTLE PRESSURED.
- AND I LIKE TO KEEP
THE LIGHT ON.
THAT WAY, I CAN SEE
IF YOU HAVE A MONSTER.
NIGHT-NIGHT.
CAN YOU SHUT THE DOOR
ON YOUR WAY OUT?
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU'RE NOT SUPPORTING THIS.
- BECAUSE IT IS OBVIOUS
WHAT SHE'S AFTER.
- OUR MONEY.
- OH, GOD! OUR MONEY.
- LET'S JUST ALL RELAX AND
REMIND OURSELVES
THAT WE DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY.
- SHE'S ALREADY GOTTEN OUR
MONEY!
- LET'S NOT FORGET SHE'S THE ONE
THAT GAVE US THE IDEA FOR THAT
OCEAN-TOP TOWN CALLED BLUTHTON.
- OH, BIG DEAL. I HAD THAT SAME
BASIC IDEA YEARS AGO.
- I THOUGHT YOU'D BE HAPPY.
I SHOULD'VE KNOWN BETTER.
- MICHAEL, BE CAREFUL.
PEOPLE JUST SEE
WHAT THEY WANT TO SEE.
IF SHE LOVED YOU,
SHE'D SHOW IT.
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS WORRIED.
HIS MOTHER MAY HAVE
BEEN MAKING SENSE.
SO HE RETURNED HOME
TO TALK TO RITA.
- HERE COMES THE BRIDE!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN A WHEELCHAIR?
- NO, NO. IT'S A DOLLY-- TO HELP
VIDEOTAPE YOUR NUPTIALS.
- [camcorder runs]
- I DON'T THINK I NEED ANY
FOOTAGE OF MY NUPTIALS.
TOBIAS, ARE YOU SURE
THAT THIS DOLLY
ISN'T RELATED
TO YOUR RECENT HEALTH PROBLEMS?
- OKAY, SO MY LEGS AND MY LEFT
ARM OCCASIONALLY "GO TO SLEEP."
AND YOU WANT TO CALL IT
A HEALTH PROBLEM.
OOP. [groaning]
- HEY. HEY, HEY!
- I CAN GET UP MYSELF.
[grunts]
- HERE WE GO.
- LET ME GET IN THE DOLLY.
NO, THANK YOU.
I DON'T NEED YOUR HELP.
- IT DOES SEEM LIKE YOU'VE
BEEN HAVING
A LOT OF TROUBLE
SINCE THE HAIR TRANSPLANTS.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD SEE
A "BUBAMAN."
- A BUBAMAN?
- OH, UH, DOCTOR.
IT'S A BRITISH EXPRESSION.
LIKE THEY SAY "GO UP BOX"
INSTEAD OF "ELEVATOR."
- OH, YES, LIKE WHEN THEY SAY
"POOFTER" TO MEAN "TOURIST."
BOY, THAT RITA'S A SMARTY.
- TRUE, BUT IT'S NOT LIKE
ANYBODY APPRECIATES IT.
MOM AND DAD DO NOT LIKE RITA.
- ARE THEY CRAZY?
SHE'S AMAZING.
I SAW HER LAST NIGHT.
SHE HELPED ME WITH
THIS PROJECT I WAS DOING.
narrator: MAEBY WAS STRUGGLING
WITH A SCREENPLAY...
IN HER SECRET LIFE
AS A FILM EXECUTIVE.
- IS THAT A STORY?
- NOT YET.
IT DOESN'T HAVE AN ENDING.
HE'S IN L.A. SHE'S IN JAPAN.
HOW DO I GET THESE TWO
CHARACTERS TOGETHER?
- MAYBE THEY COULD WALK.
- ACROSS THE OCEAN?
- IF IT'S NOT TOO DEEP.
- NO. DEEP IS GOOD.
PEOPLE ARE GONNA SAY,
"WHAT THE HELL JUST HAPPENED?
I'D BETTER SAY I LIKE IT."
'CAUSE NOBODY WANTS
TO SEEM STUPID.
- I LIKE IT.
- THE OCEAN WALKER.
HOLY CRAP.
THAT'S GONNA LOOK GOOD ON A HAT.
narrator: AND MICHAEL CAUGHT UP
WITH HIS BROTHER.
- I NEED A FAVOR.
AS YOU KNOW, I'M GETTIN' MARRIED
IN ABOUT A MONTH.
- SAY NO MORE.
- GREAT. ARE YOU SURE
THAT YOU KNOW WHAT--
- YEP, YEP, YEP. GOT IT.
SUPER.
- AND JUST SO THAT
WE'RE BOTH CLEAR--
- YOU WANT ME TO DO A MAGIC SHOW
AT THE WEDDING. I'M ON IT.
- I'M SO GLAD WE PUSHED
THROUGH THAT. NO MAGIC.
- WHY, BECAUSE OF THE ONE
LITTLE SCREWUP LAST TIME?
- PUT HER OUT! PUT HER OUT!
TRACEY! ON FIRE! ROLL!
- THANK GOD WE ALREADY
DID THE PICTURES.
- WHICH REMINDS ME THAT RITA
SHOULDN'T
WEAR ANY HAIR SPRAY
AT THIS THING.
- I JUST WANT YOU
TO BE MY WITNESS.
- YOU WANT ME TO--
BE YOUR BEST MAN?
- IT'S JUST A SIGNATURE
I NEED ON THE LICENSE.
MY SON'S NOT OLD ENOUGH.
IT'S-- IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
- I WILL NOT TAKE
THIS SACRED DUTY LIGHTLY.
I AM GONNA GET YOU
THE SINGLE HEALTHIEST CALL GIRL
THAT THIS TOWN HAS EVER SEEN.
- THIS IS WHY I'M CALLING IT
A WITNESS AND NOT A BEST MAN.
ALL YOU GOTTA DO IS WATCH.
- I'M NOT GONNA SPEND THIS KIND
OF MONEY AND NOT WATCH.
[slaps butt]
- THIS MAY HAVE BEEN A BAD
CHOICE.
HEY, HELLO. LOOK AT YOU TWO--
TWEEDLEDEE, TWEEDLEDUM.
narrator: MICHAEL DIDN'T
MEAN IT IN THAT WAY.
HOW COULD HE?
HE DIDN'T EVEN KNOW.
- WE HAD THE BEST TIME.
SHE'S GOT SUCH AN AMAZING
FASHION SENSE.
YOU GUYS GOT THESE JACKETS
ON INSIDE-OUT?
- THAT WAY, YOU SEE THE LABEL.
- YEAH, I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE PAYING FOR, RIGHT?
IT'S A GREAT STATEMENT
ON FASHION.
PLUS IT DOESN'T
TICKLE YOUR NECK.
[both laugh]
narrator: MICHAEL TOOK LINDSAY
ASIDE TO SHARE HIS CONCERNS.
- LINDSAY, WHEN DID YOU FIRST
REALIZE THAT YOU AND TOBIAS...
HAD NO CHANCE AT
A PHYSICAL RELATIONSHIP?
- OH, MY GOD.
DO YOU THINK WE HAVE NO CHANCE
AT A PHYSICAL RELATIONSHIP?
- SO, JUST NOW.
SEE, RITA AND I HAVE NOT
BEEN PHYSICAL YET, AND--
YOU DON'T THINK
SHE'S DOING THIS JUST
FOR A GREEN CARD, DO YOU?
- NO. NO, SHE'S NOT THAT KIND
OF PERSON.
YOU JUST HAVEN'T
BEEN ALONE WITH HER.
ASK HER TO STAY OVER
AT A HOTEL WITH YOU TONIGHT.
SHE'S GONNA KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS.
- THAT IS NOT A BAD IDEA.
DON'T-- DON'T DO THAT.
narrator: AND GOB BEGAN TO
PREPARE A MAGIC TRICK
FOR MICHAEL'S WEDDING.
- TAKES HIS QUEEN...
AND SHOWERS HER
WITH DIAMONDS!
CLUBS.
CLUB SAUCE.
HE COVERS HER
WITH CLUB SAUCE.
THAT'LL BE MY LINE
IF THAT HAPPENS.
- IS THAT A MAGIC TRICK?
I LOVE MAGIC.
- I DON'T APPRECIATE
THE DRY BRITISH HUMOR.
- PLEASE DO A MAGIC TRICK
FOR ME.
- WELL, I SHOULDN'T.
I'D HATE TO BE BLAMED...
FOR SETTING ANOTHER ONE OF
MICHAEL'S BRIDES...ON FIRE!
- OH. LIGHTER FLUID,
LIKE UNCLE TREVOR USES.
BUT WHEREVER
DID IT COME FROM?
- OKAY, I'VE GOTTA GET YOU
INTO AN ILLUSION AT THE WEDDING.
- HOW LONG CAN YOU
HOLD YOUR BREATH?
- OH, LONG.
ONE TIME, 20 MINUTES.
- [inhales deeply]
- narrator: ACTUALLY,
HER RECORD WAS 20 SECONDS.
- YOU CAN STOP IT. IT'S OKAY.
I'M GONNA TAKE YOUR WORD FOR IT.
[exhales]
NOW I JUST NEED TO FIND A TRICK
THAT PUTS YOU OUT OF OXYGEN FOR
20 MINUTES.
- SORRY?
DID I HEAR THE WORD "TRICK"?
AND IT SMELLS A LOT
LIKE LIGHTER FLUID IN HERE.
I DID SAY NO TRICKS, GOB,
AND I MEAN IT.
- WHAT IF I FIND A TRICK
THAT HAS HER FLOAT TO THE ALTAR
OR SOMETHING?
- NO, NO. LOVE FOR HER TO WALK
AND NOT TO DROWN...
OR FLY THROUGH THE AIR
OR CATCH ON FIRE.
- IS SHE ALLERGIC TO CAT FUR?
- UH, NO TIGERS.
- GREAT.
- SO, UH, RITA, UM,
I WAS WONDERING
IF MAYBE YOU AND I...
MIGHT HEAD DOWN
TO A HOTEL?
MAYBE SOME ALONE TIME.
- OH, YES.
- YEAH?
- MAYBE OUR ROOMS COULD TOUCH.
[chuckling]
- I--I WAS HOPING MAYBE FOR MORE
THAN JUST OUR ROOMS TO TOUCH.
I WAS THINKING MAYBE
WE COULD BE...
IN THE SAME ROOM,
BE IN THE SAME BED.
- I SEE WHAT YOU MEAN--
A REAL SLEEPOVER.
- WELL, MAYBE.
- OKAY.
- REALLY?
- MAYBE I SHOULD GO HOME
AND GET MY THINGS.
I DO KINDA MISS
MY JAMMIES.
- I THINK THEY'RE GONNA HAVE
A LOT OF THAT STUFF THERE.
- AND MY TINY TEDDY.
- GOOD.
YES, GET THAT.
narrator: AND SO GEORGE MICHAEL
DROVE RITA TO WEE BRITAIN.
- IT'S NICE TO BE
WITH SOMEONE YOUNG.
WE CAN LISTEN TO YOUNG PEOPLE'S
MUSIC FOR A CHANGE.
- GREAT.
YEAH, PLEASE.
[radio clicks on]
- [singing] HOT POTATO
HOT POTATO, HOT POTATO
- HOT POTATO, HOT POTATO
HOT POTATO
- [singing] HOT POTATO, HOT
POTATO, HOT POTATO, HOT POTATO
narrator: THAT'S WHEN
HE FIRST GREW CONCERNED.
- POTATO, POTATO, POTATO
narrator: AND RITA PACKED
FOR HER SLEEPOVER.
- DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT A SLEEPOVER IS?
'CAUSE IT'S NOT JUST SLEEP.
- I KNOW WHAT IT IS, TREVOR.
I'VE SEEN YOUR SECRET MAGAZINE.
- [singing] ALL YOU NEED IS
SMILES SMILES
- I WANT TO HAVE GROWN-UP FUN--
SPOON AND FIGGY PUDDING,
RABBIT DOWN DUM,
DRUGGERIES HOLLOW.
AND I WANT TO HAVE POP-POP.
- THE VERY FACT THAT YOU CALL IT
THAT TELLS ME YOU'RE NOT READY.
OH, AND FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
THAT'S A CRICKET MAGAZINE.
- [singing] LOTS AND LOTS
OF SMILEY SMILES
- WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT,
YOU'RE STILL A CHILD
IN MANY WAYS.
I GOT A PROBLEM WITH YOU HAVING
SEXUAL RELATIONS WITH THAT MAN.
narrator: SO DO I.
- I MEAN, IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT
YOUR PARENTS WERE COUSINS.
BUT HERE WE ARE, AND I'VE BEEN
CHARGED WITH TAKING CARE OF YOU,
AND I'M BLOODY WELL GONNA DO IT.
- WELL, MICHAEL WILL BE
MY COUSIN SOON ENOUGH,
'CAUSE WE'RE GETTING MARRIED.
- MARRIED?
- MARRIED!
- TOTALLY OUT OF THE QUESTION!
- [singsong]
MARRIED, MARRIED, MARRIED!
- ALL RIGHT, THAT DOES IT.
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
I'M PUTTIN' THE INVISIBLE
LOCKS ON THE DOOR.
- THAT'S NOT FAIR.
- LOCK, LOCK.
- THAT'S NOT FAIR!
IT'S JUST NOT FAIR!
- LOCK, LOCK.
I GOTTA FIND A NEW HIDING PLACE
FOR THAT MAGAZINE.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
WAS WAITING AT THE HOTEL.
- HEY, DAD. JUST WANTED
TO LET YOU KNOW...
THAT I'M AT A HOTEL
WITH MY WIFE-TO-BE.
AND WE'RE VERY,
VERY MUCH IN LOVE.
- PUT HER ON.
narrator: MICHAEL BRIEFLY
CONSIDERED FAKING THE VOICE.
- [falsetto] I--
SHE'S IN THE SHOWER.
- I'LL WAIT.
- LET'S WAIT.
DON'T YOU WANT ME
TO JUST CALL YOU BACK OR--
- NO. I GOT NOWHERE TO GO.
I'M UNDER HOUSE ARREST.
LET'S WATCH SOMETHING
TOGETHER.
WOW. THAT BLOSSOM
GREW UP, HUH?
SAY, HOW'S
THAT SHOWER COMIN'?
- ALL RIGHT, LOOK,
SHE'S NOT IN THE SHOWER.
- REALLY?
- SHE SAID THAT SHE'D
MEET ME AT THE HOTEL.
AND I CALLED YOU A LITTLE
PREMATURELY, BUT SHE IS COMING.
- REALLY?
- [snorts]
- UH! HEY, PUT RITA ON.
narrator: THAT'S WHEN MICHAEL
FINALLY ACCEPTED...
THAT RITA WASN'T COMING...
AND THAT LOCAL CALLS
WERE 2.95 A MINUTE.
- COME ON!
narrator:
THAT'S WHERE THEY GET YOU.
MICHAEL DROVE TO WEE BRITAIN
TO CALL OFF THE WEDDING...
THAT HE NOW REALIZED
WAS NOT BASED ON LOVE.
[knocking]
- WHO IS IT?
- IT'S MICHAEL, RITA.
CAN I COME IN?
- I CAN'T LET YOU IN.
- YOU KNOW YOU DIDN'T SHOW UP
LAST NIGHT.
I THINK THE LEAST YOU CAN DO
IS TALK TO ME FACE-TO-FACE.
- I CAN'T.
TREVOR LOCKED THE DOOR.
HE DOESN'T WANT ME
TO BE WITH YOU.
- WHAT? HE LOCKED THE DOOR?
YOU CAN'T UNLOCK THIS DOOR?
- I CAN'T EVEN SEE
HALF THE LOCKS.
- RITA? WHAT?
- THEY'RE INVISIBLE.
TREVOR'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN SEE THEM.
- I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
GO NEXT TO THE WINDOW.
I'M GONNA CLIMB UP.
- [gasps] BE CAREFUL.
- I WILL.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL SET
ABOUT RESCUING THE BEAUTIFUL,
SWEET, MENTALLY CHALLENGED
WOMAN HE'D FALLEN IN LOVE WITH,
WITHOUT REALIZING
SHE WAS MENTALLY CHALLENGED.
- YEA, MICHAEL! YEA!
- WHO UNDID THE LOCKS?
- COME ON OUT.
- TREVOR'S BACK.
- COME ON. HOP ON.
- WHAT?
- HOP ON.
- HUH?
- READY?
- OH! OH!
WHEE! OH!
- HEY! STOP THAT!
THE BOTH OF YA COME BACK!
- YOU CAN'T STOP US.
- NOTHING CAN STOP US NOW.
NOTHING IN THE WORLD OF MAN NOR
BEAST NOR TIME CAN-- [grunts]
- [applauding, cheering]
- [bleep] ALL!
narrator: AND SO,
REUNITED WITH RITA,
MICHAEL TOLD HIS PARENTS HE'D BE
GETTING MARRIED TOMORROW.
- WE'RE GETTING MARRIED
TOMORROW.
- GOD HELP HER IF SHE TRIES
TO RENAME BLUTHTON.
I'LL SINK IT FIRST. I SWEAR,
I'LL SINK THE WHOLE DAMN THING.
[phone slams]
THEY'RE GOIN' THROUGH WITH IT--
TOMORROW.
[knocking]
narrator: BUT GEORGE AND
LUCILLE HAD A SURPRISE VISITOR.
- ALL RIGHT!
WHERE THE HELL IS RITA?
I'M HER UNCLE.
- LET THE HANDOUTS BEGIN.
- THERE'S NOT GONNA BE
ANY HANDOUTS,
AND SHE IS
NOT GONNA MARRY YOUR SON.
- YOU'RE AGAINST
THIS MARRIAGE TOO.
- WELL, OF COURSE I AM.
RITA'S NOT CAPABLE OF MAKIN'
A DECISION LIKE THAT.
YOU ARE NOT GONNA GET
RITA'S MILLIONS
JUST BECAUSE
SHE'S MENTALLY CHALLENGED.
- MILLIONS?
- MENTALLY CHALLENGED?
- SHH! IT'S NOT POLITE.
- SHE OWNS ALL OF WEE BRITAIN
AND ALSO THE WEE BRITAIN
IN CLEVELAND.
'COURSE, WE'RE PROBABLY
GONNA LOSE ALL THAT...
IF HER RIDICULOUS IDEA
FOR SEA BRITAIN GOES THROUGH.
- WE ARE NOT AFTER HER MONEY.
- AND I DON'T THINK MICHAEL EVEN
KNOWS ABOUT HER...CONDITION.
- YEAH, IT'S FUNNY HOW AMERICANS
DON'T PICK UP ON THAT.
I THINK IT'S 'CAUSE OF HER
ACCENT
AND THE PLASTIC SURGERY
SHE'S BEEN ABLE TO AFFORD.
WE WOULDN'T HAVE THIS TROUBLE
IF THEY'D MET LAST YEAR.
I GOTTA PUT A STOP TO THIS.
I'M GONNA SEARCH EVERY
BLOODY HOTEL IN TOWN.
- OH! LEGOLAND.
I THINK THEY SAID...
THEY WERE GOING
TO LEGOLAND.
- THEY DID SAY LEGOLAND.
- I DIDN'T HEAR ANYTHING
ABOUT LEGOLAND.
- HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHAT HE'S TALKING ABOUT.
[whispering] WE THINK HE MAY BE
MENTALLY CHALLENGED.
- HUH?
- ALL RIGHT THEN.
- WE HAVE GOT 24 HOURS
TO GET THEM MARRIED...
[door closes]
BEFORE MICHAEL FIGURES OUT
WHAT SHE REALLY IS.
- THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
IN TWO YEARS
YOU SOUND LIKE GEORGE BLUTH.
[Buster whimpers]
narrator: LATER THAT NIGHT,
MICHAEL WAS AT THE HOTEL
WITH HIS BRIDE-TO-BE.
- RITA, I'VE BEEN REALLY
LOOKING FORWARD TO THIS.
- ME TOO.
I WANT TO HAVE
SEXUAL RELATIONS.
- THE MERE FACT
THAT YOU CALL IT THAT
TELLS ME THAT YOU ARE READY.
- THAT'S WHY I BROUGHT THIS.
- OH!
[knocking]
YOU GO AHEAD AND WHIP OUT
THAT TINY TEDDY,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA THINK UP
A FUN SAFE WORD, OKAY?
GEORGE MICHAEL, I DID NOT KNOW
THAT YOU WERE--
UM, GO AHEAD
AND TALK OUT HERE.
JUST GOT BACK FROM
THE "BUMPADDLE" COURTS.
TOMORROW,
I'M TEACHIN' HER BASEBALL.
- IT MIGHT TAKE A WHILE.
- SORRY?
- LISTEN, DAD,
TH-THIS IS...HARD--
THIS IS HARD FOR ME TO SAY.
I WAS VIDEOTAPING RITA.
LET'S JUST SAY IT WOULD BE CUTE
IF IT WAS SOMEONE MUCH YOUNGER.
[symphonic music]
[indistinct]
I'M SORRY. MAYBE
I SHOULD GET ANOTHER TAPE.
THEY'RE NOT EXPENSIVE.
- THAT'S THE PLASTIC FRUIT, DAD.
[gags]
- IT'S VERY CONVINCING FRUIT.
OKAY?
AND-- SHE'S GOIN'
BACK IN FOR ANOTHER?
YOU KNOW, THEY DON'T EVEN
HAVE BANANAS IN ENGLAND.
OKAY, SON?
NOW, I KNOW
THIS IS HARD FOR YOU,
BUT IT WOULD BE NICE
TO BE SUPPORTED IN SOME--
NOW SHE'S GOIN'
INTO THE GRAPES.
- YEAH.
SHE REALLY LIKED THOSE.
I'M SORRY.
I THINK SHE MIGHT BE...
RETAR-RETARDED.
I'M SORRY.
I'M REALLY SORRY.
- SAY HELLO TO MY TINY TEDDY.
[gasps]
TINY TEDDY? OH!
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
IT DAWNED ON MICHAEL.
- OH, YOU TEACH KIDS, HUH?
- I LIKE TO THINK
THEY TEACH ME.
THAT WAY I CAN SEE
IF YOU HAVE A MONSTER.
[gasps]
BE CAREFUL.
- I HAVE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
[loud smack]
- [laughing]
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD JUST BEEN SHOWN...
THAT HIS FIANCE
MIGHT BE MENTALLY CHALLENGED.
BUT HE NEEDED PROOF.
- SO ARE YOU READY
FOR LIE-DOWN KISSES WITH ME?
- MAYBE WE OUGHTA JUST
TALK A LITTLE BIT.
[kissing]
I MEAN, WHAT THE HECK?
FOR INSTANCE,
YOU'VE NEVER TOLD ME...
HOW MANY HOUSES THERE ARE
IN THE BRITISH PARLIAMENT.
- SEVEN.
- ARE THERE?
narrator: THE ANSWER IS THREE.
- DOES SOUND ABOUT RIGHT.
narrator:
THREE IS THE CORRECT ANSWER.
- RITA-- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
- COME ON. LET'S HAVE OUR FUN!
RITA CORNY MICHAEL.
narrator: SO MICHAEL USED A LINE
THAT WAS JUST AS CORNY.
- YOU KNOW, I THINK
THAT WE SHOULD WAIT...
UNTIL AFTER WE'RE MARRIED.
- MARRIED!
MARRIED, MARRIED, MARRIED!
OKAY!
NIGHT-NIGHT!
narrator:
AND MICHAEL FELT HE DESERVED
A $15 THING OF CANDY BEANS.
THE NEXT MORNING, HOWEVER,
AS MICHAEL PREPARED
TO LET RITA DOWN GENTLY,
HE WAS MET WITH ANOTHER
SURPRISE.
- SURPRISE!
- WHAT'S THIS?
- WE'RE THROWING YOU A WEDDING.
- [gasps] OH, HOW LOVELY!
- ON US.
EVERYTHING YOU SEE.
SHOW HIM THE WAFFLE BAR,
LARRY.
- IT'S OVER THERE.
- AND CHECK OUT BANNER, MICHAEL.
I'M GONNA GO SET UP.
- I WAS JUST GONNA TALK TO RITA
ABOUT ALL OF THIS.
RITA, I THINK THAT WE SHOULD,
UM, WAIT A LITTLE WHILE.
- WAIT? WHY?
I DON'T WANNA WAIT.
I WANT TO GET MARRIED
AND HAVE SEXUAL RELATIONS
LIKE YOU PROMISED.
- WHERE DID YOU GET
THIS FIRECRACKER?
I LOVE HER, MICHAEL.
- SO DO I. I WANNA KISS
MY NEW DAUGHTER-IN-LAW.
- HEY, NOT ON OUR TIME,
LARRY.
- RIGHT ON THE LIPS.
- NO, NO. PLEASE, TAKE IT EASY.
- I'M GONNA GET MY DRESS
FROM THE-- FROM THE ROOM.
- YES. I'LL HELP YOU
PUT IT ON INSIDE-OUT.
- LET'S-- LET'S NOT
ALL GET, UM--
MOM, WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
I THOUGHT YOU GUYS
WERE AGAINST ALL THIS.
- WELL, WE FEEL
THAT YOU KNOW BEST...
AND WHO ARE WE TO INTERFERE,
AND YOU LOVE THIS GIRL.
AND THE REST WILL JUST BE
LITTLE HAPPY SURPRISES...
ALONG THE WAY LIKE YOU SAID.
- YEAH. WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF THE RETARD THING.
- OH, GOD.
- TELL ME YOU DIDN'T
JUST SAY THAT.
- YOU KNEW?
[moans]
YOU KNEW, YET YOU STILL WANTED
ME TO GO THROUGH WITH THIS.
- WHAT CAN I SAY?
I'M CRAZY ABOUT
THE LITTLE DULLARD.
- OH, MY GOD.
SHE'S RICH.
THIS IS A NEW LOW,
EVEN FOR YOU, MOM.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
- LARRY, GO TO A MIRROR.
- YOU'RE FIRED.
- YOU'RE FIRED. WHAT?
IT'S OVER.
AND THIS IS HOW YOU TELL ME--
IN THE MIDDLE OF A WEDDING?
YOU SHOULDN'T
HAVE SAID ANYTHING.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE SAID
ANYTHING.
- YOU WERE RIGHT.
NOW WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
- I'VE BEEN THINKING.
YOU KNOW, EVERY SOCIETY HAS
THEIR OWN RULES
ABOUT THIS STUFF.
FOR INSTANCE, IN SOME STATES,
IT'S LEGAL TO MARRY
YOUR OWN COUSIN.
CALIFORNIA'S BLOCKED IT TWICE,
BUT THAT'S ONLY BECAUSE THEY
TACKED IT ONTO AN ESTATE LAW
THING THAT WASN'T GOING TO PASS.
WE HAD THE SIGNATURES THOUGH.
- YOU'RE 16,
AND YOU KNOW ALL THAT.
SHE'S 30 AND A HALF.
SHE PROBABLY CAN'T LIST
THE SEVEN HOUSES OF PARLIAMENT.
- THERE'S THREE.
- NOW I GOTTA BREAK HER HEART.
- DOESN'T SHE HAVE TO LEAVE THE
COUNTRY IF YOU DON'T MARRY HER?
- YEAH, I GUESS I CAN KEEP MY
PROMISE ABOUT THAT, HUH?
THERE WOULDN'T BE ANY
REAL INTIMACY,
AND IT WOULD BE THE STRONGEST
MARRIAGE IN THE FAMILY.
BUT AS MUCH AS I'D LIKE TO,
YOU CAN'T IGNORE THE FACT
THAT SHE IS MENTALLY DISABLED.
- OH, MY GOD.
- I'M WEARING AN INSIDE-OUT
BRIDESMAID'S DRESS.
- YOU'D BETTER CATCH HER, DAD.
- NOT GONNA BE EASY.
SHE'S AN OLYMPIC SILVER--
JUST FIGURED
THAT ONE OUT.
- OKAY. WELL, I HAVE TO GO STOP
PRODUCTION ON THE OCEAN WALKER.
- YOU FOUND OUT.
- TOOK ME LONG ENOUGH.
- MAYBE YOU'RE NOT SMART EITHER.
I DIDN'T KNOW
UNTIL THEY TOLD ME.
- NO.
I'M JUST A NARCISSIST
WHO WAS TOO SELF-INVOLVED
TO SEE THE TRUTH.
- THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
- MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
MAYBE I'M BEING
TOO HARD ON MYSELF.
YOU KNOW, THE TRUTH IS--
IS THAT I DID JUST SEE
WHAT I WANTED TO SEE.
RITA, YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL,
AND YOU'RE SO SWEET.
AND YOU DESERVE TO FIND SOMEBODY
A LOT MORE LIKE YOU.
I DON'T THINK THAT EITHER ONE OF
US WOULD BE HAPPY.
- SO, IT'S BYE-BYE
TO RITA THEN?
- UNLESS YOU REALLY WANT
TO STAY IN AMERICA.
- I WANTED TO BE WITH YOU.
- HOY! RITA!
TIME TO GO NOW.
BACK TO ENGLAND, LOVE.
- OH, MICHAEL, WILL YOU
COME VISIT ME LOTS?
- THAT'S GONNA BE DIFFICULT,
RITA.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
ACROSS AN OCEAN.
- WELL, YOU CAN ALWAYS WALK.
- NOT ON THE WATER.
- OH, MICHAEL, YOU'RE SUCH A
GROWN-UP.
[sighs]
- HEY!
HE-HEY!
HANG ON A SEC.
THAT'S PART
OF YOUR TRICK, RIGHT?
- NO. THAT'S NOT
MY TRICK, MICHAEL.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
- IT'S MY ILLUSION!
narrator: MICHAEL RELIVES
A WEDDING NIGHTMARE.
- HELP!
PUT HIM OUT!
- MY HAIR!
MY BEAUTIFUL HAIR!
- PUSH HIM IN THE POOL!
- WHY AM I NOT GOING UNDERWATER?
DEAR GOD! WHY AM I NOT
GOING UNDERWATER?