narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH PAID AN
UNEXPECTED VISIT TO HIS MOTHER.
- YOU LOOK PRETTY, MOM.
- WHAT DO YOU NEED?
- NEED? WHY DO YOU THINK
I NEED SOMETHING?
- WELL, YOU'RE TOO BUSY FOR US.
NO ONE'S SEEN YOU.
GOING ON ALL THOSE DATES
WITH RITA.
OR SHOULD I SAY PLAYDATES?
- narrator: MICHAEL
HAD RECENTLY DATED A WOMAN
HE LATER FOUND OUT
WAS MENTALLY CHALLENGED.
- WE'RE NOT SEEING EACH OTHER
ANYMORE,
BUT IT'S--
IT'S FOR THE BEST.
I'M ACTUALLY
KIND OF RELIEVED IT'S OVER.
narrator: ACTUALLY,
MICHAEL HAD BEEN SO DEVASTATED
BY THEIR BREAK-UP
THAT HE'D EVEN BROKEN OUT
THE OLD GUITAR.
- [singing] EYES, EYE--
[clatters]
[sighs]
- MAYBE YOU SHOULD TALK
TO SOMEONE.
- LIKE MY MOM?
- I DON'T KNOW.
DOES SHE PLAY GUITAR?
- CAN'T A GUY
CALL HIS MOM PRETTY
WITHOUT IT SEEMING STRANGE?
- AMEN. AND HOW ABOUT THAT
LITTLE PIECE OF TAIL ON HER?
CU-UTE!
- I'VE OPENED A DOOR HERE
THAT I REGRET.
- OH, HE'S JUST TALKING ABOUT
HIS STUPID TURTLE.
- OH.
- SHE HAS A NAME, MOTHER.
AND IT'S "MOTHER."
narrator: BUSTER HAD RECENTLY
BROUGHT HOME A TURTLE
IN AN INCREDIBLY
MISGUIDED ATTEMPT
TO MAKE HIS MOTHER JEALOUS.
- YOU CAN STAY IN THIS BOX THAT
UNCLE-FATHER OSCAR LEFT BEHIND.
narrator: IN FACT,
IT WAS A BOX OF OSCAR'S
LEGALLY OBTAINED
MEDICAL MARIJUANA.
- OH, GOOD.
HEY, IT'S ALREADY GOT GRASS.
narrator: PRIMO BUD.
REAL STICKY WEED.
- ALTHOUGH I WAS
GETTING A LITTLE WORRIED
BECAUSE SHE WAS MOVING
REALLY SLOWLY LAST WEEK,
AND THEN SHE STOPPED.
HMM.
- YEAH. WELL, IN ANY EVENT
I'M HERE, MOM,
BECAUSE YOU NEED ME.
AS YOU KNOW THE BLUTH FOUNDATION
DINNER IS A WEEK AWAY.
I AM YOUR COCHAIR,
AND WE DON'T WANNA RELIVE
THE T.B.A. DEBACLE.
narrator: YEARS EARLIER,
THE BLUTHS HAD A HARD TIME
AGREEING ON A CAUSE FOR THEIR
FOUNDATION'S FIRST FUND-RAISER.
- "HERPES."
"SHRINKAGE."
SOMEBODY SAW "SEINFELD"
LAST NIGHT.
- [chuckles]
- "NECK FLAP."
"OVARIAN CANCER."
GEE, I WONDER WHO THAT WAS?
ONE MORE FOR "NECK FLAP."
- YES.
- WELL, I'LL BE HONEST.
I HAVEN'T HEARD ANYTHING
THAT BEATS HERPES.
narrator: SO THEY SENT OUT
INVITATIONS WITH THE DISEASE
STILL "TO BE ANNOUNCED."
AND MUCH TO THEIR SURPRISE,
THE BLUTHS ENDED UP RAISING
OVER $25,000 TO FIGHT T.B.A.
AND THEN--AND HERE'S
THE REALLY HORRIBLE PART--
THEY DID IT AGAIN
THE FOLLOWING YEAR.
- KEEP FIGHTING, LITTLE GUY.
WITH YOUR SUPPORT
OF THE BLUTH FOUNDATION,
WE'LL LIVE IN A GALAXY
WHERE T.B.A. DOES NOT EXIST.
- WHEN PEOPLE AT THE LAST GALA
FOUND OUT,
WE ALMOST HAD
A RIOT ON OUR HANDS.
- WELL, YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT ANYTHING LIKE THAT
THIS YEAR,
BECAUSE WARDEN GENTLES
IS THE NEW COCHAIR.
- THE GUY WHO RAN DAD'S PRISON?
- HE'S HERE NOW
INSTALLING CAMERAS
BECAUSE OF ALL YOUR FATHER'S
ESCAPE ATTEMPTS.
- UH, YEAH, LOOKS LIKE
I WON'T BE GOIN' ANYWHERE
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
BUT WHAT DO I CARE, HUH?
I GOT A BEAUTIFUL WIFE.
I GOT A WONDERFUL HOBBY.
HA! LOOK AT ME.
I'M HAVING THE TIME OF MY LIFE.
narrator: HIS HOBBY WAS MAKING
PAPIER-MACHE COPIES
OF HIS OWN HEAD.
- BEFORE I FORGET, DO YOU KNOW
IF THESE CAMERAS ARE HIGH DEF?
- I CERTAINLY HOPE SO.
IT'LL HELP ME BETTER
UNDERSTAND "GEORGE BLUTH,"
THE MAIN CHARACTER OF THE LATEST
AND, I PRAY, FINAL DRAFT
OF MY SCREENPLAY, "NEW WARDEN."
- YOU WROTE A SCREENPLAY, HUH?
- I PROMISED MYSELF I WASN'T
GONNA BECOME
ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE
WHO ARE ALWAYS GOING ON
ABOUT THEIR SCREENPLAYS,
SO I'LL JUST SAY,
I PUT TOGETHER A STAGED READING
WITH SOME FABULOUS YOUNG ACTORS,
AND IT WAS
VERY WELL RECEIVED.
narrator: WARDEN GENTLES
HAD CONVINCED
HIS GRANDDAUGHTER'S TEACHER
TO MOUNT "NEW WARDEN"
AS A SCHOOL PLAY.
- I UNDERSTAND YOU'VE
BEEN CAUSING PROBLEMS.
NOBODY SELLS ANY COKE
IN THIS PEN
WITHOUT DADDY
GETTING A TASTE.
BEAT HIM WITH A PILLOWCASE
FULL OF BATTERIES.
- WARD'S LETTING US
HOLD THE EVENT
IN THE NEW WING OF THE PRISON.
AFTER LOCKDOWN, EVERYONE'S GOING
TO SPEND THE NIGHT IN A CELL.
[others laughing]
- ARE THEY COLOR
OR BLACK AND WHITE?
- SO, MICHAEL, I DON'T NEED
YOUR HELP AT ALL--
UNLESS YOU NEED SOMETHING
FROM ME?
- NO. I'M FINE.
JUST THOUGHT I COULD HELP.
RELIEVED I DON'T HAVE TO.
narrator:
BUT HE WASN'T RELIEVED.
SO HE WENT HOME TO COMPLAIN
TO HIS SISTER, LINDSAY.
- PRISON'S THE LAST THING
WE WANT PEOPLE ASSOCIATING
WITH THE BLUTH NAME.
PLUS, WHO'S GONNA WANT TO GO?
- WAIT, THIS IS GONNA BE
AT THE PRISON?
OH, GREAT. PROBABLY GONNA
RUN INTO THAT WARDEN.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW THE WARDEN?
- OH, RIGHT.
UH, HE SPOKE AT MY SCHOOL FOR
A "STARTLED STRAIGHT" ASSEMBLY.
narrator: ACTUALLY, SHE'D MET
WITH HIM IN THE HOPES
OF USING HIS PRISON
AS A LOCATION FOR A FILM.
- I THINK YOU WILL FIND
THE DESSERT
BOTH ENGROSSING
AND HIGH GROSSING.
- SO WE DON'T GET DESSERT.
I GUESS I HAVE
SOME READING TO DO.
- BESIDES I DOUBT VERY MUCH
MOM'S COME UP
WITH A REAL DISEASE
TO HAVE A FUND-RAISER FOR.
- I FORGOT.
WE HAVE A REAL DISEASE.
I CHOSE IT: G.V.H.,
"GRAFT VERSUS HOST."
IT'S NEW, IT'S FATAL,
AND GUESS WHO'S GOT IT?
- YOU'VE HEARD OF BODIES
REJECTING TRANSPLANTS.
WELL, IN THIS CASE,
YOUR TRANSPLANTED HAIR
IS REJECTING YOUR BODY.
EITHER YOU REMOVE
YOUR HAIR GRAFT,
OR THE HOST, YOU, WILL GET
SICKER AND EVENTUALLY DIE.
- CAN YOU THINK OF ANY BENEFITS?
- BENEFITS?
NO. HE'LL DIE.
- OH, OH, YEAH. NO, I--
I GET THAT.
BUT HAVE THERE
EVER BEEN ANY FUND-RAISERS?
A HUSBAND
WITH THE HEADLINING DISEASE.
EVERYONE'S GONNA
WANNA TALK TO ME.
- YOU'RE MAKING HIM
KEEP THE HAIR?
- DID YOU SEE THE ATTENTION
SUPERMAN'S WIFE GOT?
BESIDES, TOBIAS WANTS IT TOO.
- OH, SHE'S RIGHT.
THIS IS GONNA BE GREAT FOR
ME, BECAUSE I AM GONNA STAR
IN THE VIDEO GOB'S MAKING
FOR THE GALA.
- OH, YEAH.
IT'LL BE VERY UPLIFTING.
OH, HERE, LET ME
GET THAT FOR YOU.
- THANK YOU.
OH. OH, THIS IS GONNA HURT.
OH!
crash!
thud!
OOP.
- YOU KNOW WHAT? WE'RE GONNA
NEED THIS FROM ANOTHER ANGLE.
- AND YOU'RE SURE
YOU'RE OKAY?
- OH, PROBABLY.
I CAN'T FEEL ANYTHING.
HOW'S MY HAIR?
- IT'S FINE.
IT'S SUCKING THE LIFE
OUT OF YOU, TOBIAS.
I MEAN, EVERYTHING'S GONE
CRAZY--
THE GALA,
MOM AND WARDEN GENTLES.
I MEAN, WHAT IS IN IT FOR HIM?
I THINK HE'S TAKING
ADVANTAGE OF MOM.
- AND DID IT EVER OCCUR TO YOU
THAT MAYBE WARDEN GENTLES
LIKES HER?
- LIKES HER WHAT?
- NO, I--I MEAN, LIKES HER,
LIKE, IS ATTRACTED TO HER.
- WHO'S THE "HER"
IN THAT SENTENCE?
- MOM. WARDEN GENTLES LIKES MOM.
- HER?
- I'M AFRAID
I'M WITH MICHAEL ON THIS.
THE GUY RUNS A PRISON.
HE CAN HAVE ANY PIECE
OF ASS HE WANTS.
- AND IF HE LIKES HER IN THAT
SENSE, IT MAKES IT EVEN WORSE.
I DON'T WANT MOM MIXED UP
WITH THE SORT OF CREEP
THAT WOULD HAVE HER AS A FETISH.
- OH, MICHAEL,
YOU'RE JUST FEELING NEGLECTED
BY YOUR MOTHER.
YOU WANTED TO GO TO THIS
WITH HER, DIDN'T YOU?
- HEY, I--I DON'T NEED
TO TAKE MY MOM TO A GALA, OKAY?
ONLY LOSERS GO TO THOSE
THINGS WITH THEIR PARENTS.
I'M GOING WITH MY SON.
- OH, I MAY SKIP THAT.
I DON'T LIKE GALAS.
narrator:
ACTUALLY, HE LOVED GALAS.
ALL KIDS DO.
- OH, COME ON. DON'T LEAVE
YOUR UNCLE TEA BAG HANGIN'.
- PLEASE DON'T
CALL YOURSELF THAT.
narrator: WHAT HE WAS HAVING
TROUBLE WITH
WAS LOOKING DIRECTLY
AT HIS DYING UNCLE.
- I CAN'T STAND BY
AND WATCH MOM GET HURT.
I GOTTA GET DOWN THERE.
- THIS IS HEARTBREAKING.
GOTTA GET THIS
FOR THE VIDEO.
HEY, GEORGE MICHAEL,
YOU WANNA PUT YOUR HEAD DOWN
THERE BY HIS DRAINAGE SHUNT?
narrator: BUSTER, MEANWHILE,
WAS ALSO FEELING ABANDONED
BY MOTHER.
- MO--MOTHER!
I HAVE NO ONE NOW.
narrator:
BUT AT THAT VERY MOMENT,
HIS TRUE FATHER RETURNED.
- [gasps]
UNCLE-FATHER OSCAR,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- [sighs]
WELL, YOU KNOW ME.
I COULD NEVER
LEAVE A LITTLE BUD BEHIND.
OH, A HUG. NICE.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN A LITTLE BOX
WITH A TURTLE ON IT, HAVE YOU?
- OH, YEAH. MY TURTLE
WAS LIVING IN IT
BEFORE HE ATE ALL THE GRASS
AND DIED.
- HE ATE ALL THE GRASS?
- YEAH.
- WELL, IT'S BEEN GREAT
CATCHING UP.
- W-W-WAIT, WHERE YOU GOING?
- NO, I CAN'T STAY,
BECAUSE IF MY BROTHER FINDS OUT
THAT I'M HERE,
HE'S GONNA TRY SWITCHING
PLACES AGAIN,
AND I CAN'T
GO BACK TO PRISON.
- WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
IF MY FATHER COMES IN, YOU CAN
HIDE IN ONE OF GOB'S TRICKS.
- I CAN'T.
- AT LEAST YOU CAN STAY AND
HELP ME BURY MY POOR TURTLE.
- OR WE COULD CREMATE IT.
narrator: AND MAEBY
WAS HAVING A HARDER TIME
FINISHING WARDEN GENTLE'S
SCREENPLAY THAN HE DID.
- YOU'RE A READER.
HOW'D YOU LIKE
TO READ SOMETHING FUN
THAT WE COULD TALK ABOUT
ON THE WAY TO THE PRISON GALA?
- OH, I'M ACTUALLY GONNA
SIT THAT OUT.
I'M JUST BURNT OUT
ON PRISONS LATELY.
- WELL, THIS MIGHT
CHANGE YOUR MIND.
- IS THAT A SCREENPLAY?
- WELL, THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME.
narrator: AND MICHAEL RACED
TO WARN HIS MOTHER
OF THE WARDEN'S INTENTIONS.
- HEY! YOU CAN'T PARK THERE.
- OH, SORRY.
I'M SORRY.
- NO STAIRS.
NO PARKING.
- [screams]
- SORRY.
- EVERYTHING LOOKS DELICIOUS.
- OH, ONE-EYE'S
A WONDERFUL CHEF.
I'VE HAD TO GO TO HIS PAROLE
HEARINGS TWICE
AND LIE THROUGH
MY TEETH TO KEEP HIM HERE.
- [cackling]
- HI, I JUST, UM--
WOW.
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS DOING?
- IT'S PERFECTLY INNOCENT,
BUT I CAN SEE HOW
IF OUR ROLES WERE REVERSED,
I MIGHT HAVE YOU BEATEN
WITH A PILLOWCASE
FULL OF BATTERIES.
I'LL GIVE YOU TWO A MOMENT.
- THANK YOU.
- I DON'T KNOW WHY
I ALWAYS ASSUME
THAT EVERYONE'S READ
MY SCREENPLAY.
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
THAT MAN IS BEING
WONDERFUL TO US.
- AND THAT DOESN'T CONCERN YOU,
MOTHER?
FOR ALL YOU KNOW, HE COULD BE
TRYING TO SEDUCE YOU.
- OH, MICHAEL, YOU'RE CRAZY.
- I CERTAINLY HOPE SO.
- I'M TRYING TO SEDUCE HIM.
- WHO'S THE "I" IN THAT
SENTENCE?
- ME.
- YOU?
- narrator: HER.
MICHAEL HAD JUST DISCOVERED
THAT HIS MOTHER WAS INTERESTED
IN ANOTHER MAN.
- MOM WANTS TO SLEEP
WITH THE WARDEN.
- WHAT? OH, GOD!
- GREAT.
- GREAT? THE MAN IS OLD ENOUGH
TO BE HER CONTEMPORARY,
LINDSAY.
PLUS, SHE'S MARRIED, OKAY?
SHE CAN'T BE WRITHING AROUND
UNDERNEATH THE COVERS--
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
IT'S DISGUSTING! GOD!
- TAKE IT EASY.
- NO, IT'S JUST I'VE ALWAYS
HAD A THING
ABOUT MOM AND DAD
BEING TOGETHER.
- I KNOW THAT.
- I HAVE A SENSE
OF PROPRIETY, MY GOD.
- GOB, WE'VE HAD
THIS CONVERSATION.
- WHEN?
- THE LAST TIME YOU ENDED UP
SEEING MOM AND DAD GO AT IT.
- WHAT? NO! GOD, MICHAEL!
I DID NO SUCH THING.
- narrator:
HE DID VERY MUCH THAT THING
WHEN HIS PARENTS GOT INTIMATE
IN A CONJUGAL TRAILER
TWO YEARS AGO.
BUT THANKFULLY, HE'D FOUND
A WAY TO FORGET THAT.
- I GOT A THING OF PILLS
IN MY POCKET.
I DON'T SUPPOSE I COULD
CONVINCE YOU TO GRAB ME ONE.
narrator:
LUCKILY, THAT WORKED TOO.
- I CAN'T EVEN HEAR THIS.
- YOU MAY NOT LIKE IT
THAT MOM HAS NEEDS,
BUT IT NEVER BOTHERED YOU
WHEN DAD WAS RUNNING AROUND.
- WELL, THAT WAS DIFFERENT.
- WELL, HOW 'BOUT WHEN SHE WAS
SLEEPING WITH UNCLE OSCAR?
- THE GUY LOOKS JUST LIKE DAD.
I DON'T KNOW. HE'S FAMILY.
IT SEEMED VERY NATURAL
THEY'D BE TOGETHER.
- WHO? WHAT? WHAT IS NATURAL?
IS THERE NEW LEGISLATION
ON THIS NOW?
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS CONCERNED ABOUT FAMILY LOVE
AFTER READING MAEBY'S SCRIPT,
WHICH HE TOOK AS A SUBTLE
MESSAGE TO HIM FROM HIS COUSIN.
- LISTEN, NEW FISH.
THAT BUNK WAS OPEN
BECAUSE THE LAST GUY
WOULDN'T DO THE THINGS
THAT YOU'RE GOING TO DO.
- WE'RE GOING TO DO THINGS?
- ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN WHEN
TWO PEOPLE SHARE A CELL, COZ.
- UM, I'LL GO--OKAY, I'LL GO
WITH YOU TO THE PRISON.
- GEORGE MICHAEL, WHAT I WANT
YOU TO DO IS RUN UPSTAIRS
AND RUN A NICE BATH
FOR UNCLE TOBIAS.
AND I WANT YOU TO HELP HIM
GET IN THE TUB.
CAN YOU DO THAT FOR ME?
THANKS.
- AND DON'T MAKE
THE WATER TOO HOT.
THE SCABS COME RIGHT OFF.
- COME ON, LINDSAY. WHAT ARE
WE GONNA DO ABOUT MOTHER?
- HONESTLY, MICHAEL,
ALL THIS "MOTHER" TALK--
YOU'RE STARTING TO SOUND
A LOT LIKE BUSTER.
narrator: AND MICHAEL REALIZED
THERE WAS SOMEBODY ELSE
IN THE FAMILY
WHO WOULD CARE ABOUT THIS.
- BUSTER'S GONNA TAKE THIS
SO HARD.
I CANNOT LET
MY BROTHER GET HURT.
- OH!
[grunting]
- OH, IT'S ON STANDBY.
GOT ANOTHER ONE IN YOU?
- [groaning]
narrator: BUSTER, MEANWHILE,
WAS ENJOYING BEING WITH OSCAR.
BUT OSCAR WAS LONGING
FOR HIS SWEET FREEDOM.
- SAY, YOU DON'T HAVE ANY
SWEET FREEDOM OR TROPICAL EASE
OR ANY OF THE HAWAIIAN BLENDS,
DO YOU?
[door closes]
SOMEONE'S COMING.
- OH, DAD, GET IN THE CAGE
AND HIDE BEHIND THE MIRROR.
IT'LL LOOK EMPTY.
narrator: OSCAR
NEVER GOT A CHANCE
TO HIDE BEHIND THE MIRROR.
- [grunts]
narrator: ALTHOUGH IT WAS NOT
THE FIRST TIME
HE WAS KNOCKED OUT
BY A POWERFUL LID.
- HEY, BUSTER, LISTEN.
I GOT SOME BAD NEWS
ABOUT MOM.
SHE'S PLANNING ON SPENDING THE
NIGHT WITH ANOTHER MAN.
- GOB?
- N-NO. NOT ANOTHER BROTHER.
- OH.
THEN WHY DO WE CARE?
- WHAT IS WRONG WITH EVERYONE?
UH, B-BUSTER, YOU'VE GOT
TO TALK TO MOM ABOUT THIS.
SHE CAN'T POSSIBLY DO IT.
IF DAD FINDS OUT,
HE'LL GO BERSERK.
- IF DAD FINDS OUT ABOUT WHAT?
- OH. WELL, I GUESS
I'VE GOT NO CHOICE NOW.
DAD, I-I'VE GOT SOME BAD NEWS
ABOUT MOM
AND WARDEN GENTLES DATING.
- OH. BETTER SIT DOWN.
[breathing heavily]
OKAY, WHAT'S THE NEWS?
- THEY'RE DATING.
- OH, YEAH. BECAUSE SHE'S--
SHE'S MY WIFE.
OH, YEAH. DAMN IT!
- I'M SURPRISED YOU'RE NOT
MORE UPSET ABOUT THIS.
- WHEN YOU FIRST TOLD ME, BUT
YOU SEE, TIME--TIME PASSES.
BESIDES, IT'S ONLY,
UH, DINNER IN THE OFFICE.
I MEAN IT'S NOT LE CIRQUE.
- HOW'D YOU KNOW
THAT IT WAS IN HIS OFFICE?
- WELL, WH-WHERE--
WHERE THE HELL ELSE
ARE THEY GONNA GO
AT 4:00 IN THE AFTERNOON?
- IT WAS AROUND 4:00.
YOU ALREADY KNOW ABOUT THIS.
COME ON.
YOU'RE UP TO SOMETHING, RIGHT?
- NO.
- YOU BOTH ARE.
SHE'S WORKIN' THE WARDEN.
YOU'RE MAKIN' FAKE HEADS.
YOU'RE PLANNING AN ESCAPE.
- HOW DARE YOU?
I OUGHTA SHAVE YOUR HEAD
AND MAKE YOU SIT UNDER
THAT CAMERA ALL NIGHT, MISTER.
- IT'S UNBELIEVABLE. YOU KNOW,
I WAS WORRIED THAT THIS GUY
WAS GONNA TAKE ADVANTAGE OF MOM.
YOU BOTH WERE TAKING ADVANTAGE
OF HIM.
I DON'T KNOW WHY I WORK
SO DAMN HARD
TO KEEP THIS FAMILY TOGETHER.
- MICHAEL, CAN I TALK TO YOU
FOR ONE SEC?
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN GEORGE
SR. GOT A CALL FROM LUCILLE.
- THREE, TWO, TWO, FIVE, TWO.
[beeps]
- HOWDY DOODY, THAT'S IT.
NOW, Y-YOU GET BACK HERE
SO YOU CAN SMUGGLE ME OUT
PAST THE GUARDS
BEFORE MICHAEL STARTS BLABBING.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU CAN SMUGGLE YOURSELF OUT.
YOU WANNA GET AWAY FROM ME
SO BAD? YOU'RE FREE.
BUT I'M FREE TOO, BABY.
I'M STAYING IN THE CONJUGAL
TRAILER WITH THE WARDEN TONIGHT.
- HIM?
- HEY, WHY IS THERE
AN AMBULANCE OUT FRONT?
- HONEY, THE CAR IS HERE.
- HEY, DO YOU NEED A RIDE?
I MEAN, YOU'LL HAVE TO
LIE DOWN, BUT--
- I'M NOT GOIN'.
THE WHOLE THING IS A SCAM.
MOM WAS USING THAT WARDEN
TO TRY TO GET DAD OUT.
SHE'S NOT TRYING
TO SEDUCE HIM AT ALL.
- OH, NO. SHE IS.
SHE'S SPENDING THE NIGHT
WITH HIM.
SHE JUST CALLED TO ASK ME TO
BRING HER A TUBE OF VAG--
IS-TABLE PASTE.
HI, GEORGE MICHAEL.
- YOU'RE GOIN' TOO, HUH?
- YEAH. I THOUGHT I WOULD, UM,
JUST GO WITH MAEBY
AND SUPPORT HER THROUGH THIS
WHOLE GRAFT VERSUS HOST THING.
narrator: AND MICHAEL HIMSELF
WAS FEELING A LITTLE LIKE
THE HOST THAT THE GRAFTING
FAMILY WAS REJECTING.
- GOOD. GREAT. GO.
IT'S A VERY IMPORTANT CAUSE.
I'LL JUST STAY HERE AND READ.
narrator: BUT THIS, TOO,
WOULD PROVE CHALLENGING
AS THE FAMILY HAD NO BOOKS.
OTHER THAN THOSE.
AND THAT'S WHEN MICHAEL
GOT A GLIMPSE
INTO THE WARDEN'S TRUE
INTENTIONS WITH HIS MOTHER.
- YOU WERE JUST USING ME
TO GET EVEN WITH THE MAN
WHO BROKE OUT OF YOUR PRISON?
- THAT ESCAPE COST ME
MY PROMOTION.
AND YOU WILL PAY FOR
THE LOSS OF $2,300 A YEAR.
- BUT YOU GAVE ME PRESENTS.
WE MADE LOVE.
- I'VE GIVEN YOU
ONE LAST PRESENT.
ENJOY THE CHLAMYDIA, LUCILLE.
HA, HA, HA.
TAKE THIS NEWLY DISEASED WOMAN
TO THE HOLE. HA, HA, HA.
- I WISH I'D READ
"THE MAN INSIDE ME."
narrator:
GEORGE SR. NEEDED TO ESCAPE,
BUT HIS HANDMADE REPLICA
WOULD NEVER FOOL THE CAMERAS.
SO HE SEARCHED
THROUGH GOB'S MAGIC STUFF
TO FIND SOMETHING THAT MIGHT.
- WELL, THAT WAS A FREEBIE.
- HEY, GOB,
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
I THOUGHT YOU'D BE AT THE GALA.
- YEAH, DAD MADE ME MOVE MY
STUFF OUTTA BUSTER'S ROOM.
narrator: BUT ONLY AFTER
HIDING HIMSELF IN THE CAGE
TO GET PAST THE COPS
AT THE DOOR.
- GO.
- MOM'S BEING SET UP. WE HAVE
TO GET INTO THAT PRISON.
- IT'S AFTER LOCKDOWN.
- COME ON, GOB. YOU WERE GONNA
BREAK OUT OF THIS PLACE ONCE.
I KNOW YOU CAN HELP ME BREAK IN.
- [scoffs]
IT'S NOT A JAMBA JUICE, MICHAEL.
IT SHOULDN'T BE THAT HARD
TO BREAK INTO.
narrator: AND BUSTER RETURNED
ONLY TO FIND
NO EVIDENCE OF HIS UNCLE-FATHER.
- [mumbles]
- HEY, FATHER-UNCLE DAD,
I WAS JUST BRINGIN'
SOME JUICE FOR MY PET.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE NOT REALLY SMILING.
- I'M OSCAR.
HE DID IT AGAIN.
I TOLD YOU HE WOULD.
I CAN'T GO THROUGH THIS AGAIN.
I CAN'T BE CAGED!
narrator: AND BUSTER REALIZED
HE NEEDED TO GIVE HIS TRUE
FATHER HIS FREEDOM.
- HEY! LET'S GET HIM!
narrator: BUT IT WAS A FREEDOM
THAT DIDN'T LAST LONG.
AND AS THE PRISON GALA
WAS UNDERWAY,
THE GUYS ARRIVED FOR THEIR
BREAK-IN, WITH THE HELP
OF ONE OF GEORGE SR.'S
INSTRUMENTS OF ESCAPE.
- YOU THINK THIS IS GONNA WORK?
- IT'S A JET PACK, MICHAEL.
WHAT COULD POSSIBLY GO WRONG?
ALL RIGHT.
- NOW JUST MAKE SURE YOU TELL ME
BEFORE YOU HIT ANY BUTTONS--
- GOOD. NOW WE KNOW
WHAT THE STRAP IS FOR.
- OKAY.
- UNDER THE CROTCH.
- WE NEED A NEW PLAN.
- YUP.
- WISH I KNEW THE LAYOUT
OF THIS PLACE.
- WAY AHEAD OF YOU, MICHAEL.
DREW A MAP OF IT ON MY STOMACH.
IT'S UPSIDE DOWN, SO IT MIGHT
BE A LITTLE AWKWARD.
narrator: IT WAS AWKWARD.
- I DREW US.
I THINK WE'RE, LIKE,
RIGHT THERE.
- HEY, GUYS.
IF YOU'RE GONNA PARTY,
YOU WANNA BRING IT INSIDE?
- THAT WAS A FREEBIE.
- WELL, THE NEW FACILITY
ISN'T SO BAD, HUH?
IT'S A LOT LIKE SCHOOL,
ONLY IT'S AIR-CONDITIONED.
SO I GUESS WE CAN JUST, UH--
JUST CHOOSE A CELL TO STAY
OVERNIGHT IN AND, UH--
- OH, GREAT. AND YOU CAN TAKE ME
THROUGH YOUR THOUGHTS
ABOUT THE SCREENPLAY
BEAT BY BEAT.
- SURE. YEAH. "BECAUSE
ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN
WHEN TWO PEOPLE
SHARE A CELL, COZ."
IT'S A LINE FROM--
FROM "NEW WARDEN."
- OH. OH!
OKAY, YEAH. I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I WAS WORRIED ABOUT.
narrator: THAT WOULD BE
THE HAPPIEST MOMENT
GEORGE MICHAEL WOULD EVER
EXPERIENCE IN HIS LIFE.
AND THE WARDEN WAS HAPPY TOO.
- WHAT A TREAT.
THE MAN WHO COST ME MY PROMOTION
ENDS UP BACK IN MY CARE.
AND I DON'T THINK
THERE'S GOING TO BE
AN "I'M OSCAR" WEB SITE
THIS TIME.
- THINK THIS TIME
I'LL DO A PODCAST.
- "GRAFT VERSUS HOST."
SOUNDS LIKE A TENNIS MATCH
BETWEEN STEFFI GRAF AND "HAPPY
DAYS" STAR DONNY HOST.
narrator:
IT'S "MOST."
- BUT IT'S FAR DEADLIER.
HELLO. I'M GOB BLUTH.
AS A MAGICIAN, I CAN MAKE
A LOT OF THINGS DISAPPEAR.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
I CAN'T MAKE DISAPPEAR--
NO, NOT THAT
CANDY BALL MACHINE--
THE DISEASE G.V.H.
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
THIS IS TOBIAS.
WHEN TOBY
FIRST CAME INTO THE FAMILY,
NONE OF US MUCH
WANTED HIM AROUND,
BUT THAT'S BECAUSE WE COULDN'T
SEE WHAT WAS ON THE INSIDE.
BUT LATELY, THAT'S ALL
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO SEE.
[woman gagging]
BUT WHAT WAS TOBIAS TO DO--
[crowd groans]
HAVE HIS HAIR PLUGS REMOVED?
- THE DOCTOR SAYS
I'D BE COMPLETELY HEALED
IF I WERE TO DO THAT.
- HE JUST NEEDS
HIS HAIR PLUGS OUT?
- DOCTOR SAYS THAT'S THE CURE.
- THERE'S A CURE?
- NO WAY. THAT HORSEHAIR IS
MY TICKET BACK INTO SOCIETY.
YOU CUT IT AFTER THOSE IDIOTS
AT THE GALA
ACCEPT ME
AS ONE OF THEIR OWN.
- WE'RE GIVING MONEY
FOR THIS GUY
TO KEEP HIS HAIR TRANSPLANTS?
- I'D RATHER GIVE TO T.B.A.!
- [bleep]
narrator:
THE CROWD BEGAN TO GROW UNRULY.
- WE HAVE A RIOT
IN THE BALLROOM.
narrator: AND, JUST AS THE
PRISONERS HAD PROVEN
THEY COULD THROW A GALA
AS WELL AS THE RICH,
SO THE RICH PROVED
THEY COULD THROW A RIOT
JUST AS WELL AS THE PRISONERS.
AND LUCILLE WAS BROUGHT
TO THE CONJUGAL TRAILER.
- MOM.
- MICHAEL, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I CANNOT LET YOU
GO THROUGH WITH THIS.
YOU CAN'T SLEEP WITH HIM.
- OH, YES I CAN.
I'M MAKING UP FOR THE HEARTBREAK
YOUR FATHER HAS CAUSED ME.
HE DOESN'T NEED ME.
YOU DON'T NEED ME.
- OF COURSE I NEED YOU, MOM.
MY HEART IS KIND OF BROKEN TOO.
I'VE BEEN KIND OF
DENYING IT LATELY, BUT,
UM, YOU KNOW,
IT JUST--I CAN'T--
I CAN'T DEAL WITH THE FACT
THAT MY FAMILY'S FALLING APART,
NOW THAT I REALLY NEED YOU.
- OH, MICHAEL, HONEY.
I WANNA CRY SO BAD,
BUT I DON'T THINK
I CAN SPARE THE MOISTURE.
- WELL, LISTEN. HERE'S--
THE PROBLEM IS THAT, UH, GENTLES
DOESN'T REALLY CARE FOR YOU.
HE'S JUST USING YOU TO GET BACK
AT DAD FOR ESCAPING,
AT LEAST ACCORDING TO HIS
SCREENPLAY.
- YOU READ IT?
- YEAH.
- DID YOU LIKE THE CHLAMYDIA
THING? I GAVE HIM THAT.
- YOU GAVE HIM CHLAMYDIA?
- HE HAD "CRABS," AND I SAID,
"YOU'RE GONNA GET LAUGHS."
- THEN WHAT AM I DOING?
I MEAN, IF DAD DOESN'T CARE,
THERE'S--THERE'S NO REAL THREAT
AND, I GUESS, JUST
KNOCK YOURSELF OUT, HUH?
- WHERE'S GENTLES?
I'LL KILL HIM!
- GEORGE?
- DAD?
- I CAN'T LET YOU DO THIS.
I CAN'T LET WHAT WE HAVE--
AS LOUSY AS IT MAY BE
AT TIMES--BE DESTROYED.
- THIS IS WHERE YOU ESCAPED TO?
TO PRISON? FOR ME?
- NO ONE IS BREAKING
THIS FAMILY APART.
NO ONE.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK I NEEDED TO HEAR THAT.
- SORRY ABOUT THE WAIT.
GEORGE?
IF YOU'RE HERE, WHO DO WE HAVE
IN THE DELOUSING TANK?
- I'M GUESSING OSCAR.
- NO.
I CANNOT TAKE
ANOTHER $2,300 HIT.
- I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU LET OSCAR OUT,
AND YOU GIVE US AN HOUR IN HERE,
AND, UH,
WE'LL CALL IT EVEN.
- PLEASE, WARD?
- I CAN'T SAY NO TO THE WOMAN
WHO GAVE ME "CHLAMYDIA."
ONE HOUR.
- ARE YOU READY
TO HAVE SOME FUN?
- I AM SO GLAD I DIDN'T CRY.
- THAT I DIDN'T NEED TO HEAR.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
GEORGE MICHAEL
GETS CLOSER TO HIS FAMILY.
[alarm buzzes]
- LOCKDOWN!
- THAT WAS CLOSE, HUH, MAEBY?
- OH, SHE'S IN THE NEXT CELL.
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE GONNA BE
BUNK BUDDIES ALL NIGHT, COZ.
[coughing]
- narrator:
GEORGE MICHAEL EXPERIENCES
HIS UNHAPPIEST MOMENT EVER.
BUSTER TRIES TO FORGET
HIS RECENT LOSSES--
- [singing] JUST--
narrator: BY BREAKING OUT
THE OLD GUITAR,
AND GOB FINALLY FACES
A PHOBIA HE'D FACED BEFORE.
- NO! NOT HERE!
WAIT, I'VE SEEN THIS BEFORE.
OH, GOD, I'VE SEEN THIS BEFORE!
AH!
[taser buzzing]