[narrator]
NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING...
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE...
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS TRYING TO INCLUDE
HIS BROTHER IN THE BUSINESS,
AT HIS FATHER'S REQUEST--
- SO, THE LAST COUPLE
OF MONTHS HAVE SEEN US
HEMORRHAGING MONEY--
[loud pop]
[narrator]
BUT HE WAS FINDING HIMSELF
OVERWHELMED BY THE CHANGE.
- IS IT MY TURN TO SPEAK YET?
I'VE GOT A GOOD ONE.
- WE'RE GONNA WAIT TILL
AFTER LUNCH FOR THE TRICKS.
- IT'S NOT A TRICK, MICHAEL.
IT'S A BUSINESS OPPORTUNITY.
[disco]
YOU CAN TURN THE MUSIC OFF.
I ALREADY SHOT MY WAD.
OFF.
[Franklin singing]
NO, THAT'S
IT'S A-- TAPE.
[stops]
I HAVE GOT
A QUICK WAY FOR US...
TO LITERALLY BE SHOWERED
WITH MONEY.
THAT'S WHERE
THE PENNY THING WOULD HAVE--
[loud pop]
BONUS. ANYWAY, IT INVOLVES
US MAKING SOME MONEY...
WITH OUR MEXICAN FRIENDS
FROM COLOMBIA.
- I THINK THEY'RE CALLED
COLOMBIANS.
OH, I FORGOT. WE'RE BEING
"POLITICALLY CORRECT."
[loud pop]
[glass shattering]
ANYWAY, THERE'S A COMPANY THERE
THAT WANTS TO DEVELOP
SOME TIME-SHARES WITH US.
I TOLD THEM THAT WE'LL
SELL THEM OUR BLUEPRINTS...
FOR 100 GRAND.
- GOB, WE'RE PROHIBITED...
FROM DOING ANY BUSINESS
OUTSIDE THE COUNTRY WHILE
WE'RE UNDER INVESTIGATION.
- TRANSLATION:
"WISH I'D THOUGHT OF THAT."
- NICE TRANSLATING, DAD.
- OH.
I ALSO HAD THIS SLOGAN
MADE UP.
"A COLOMBIAN CARTEL THAT WON'T
KIDNAP AND KILL YOU."
UNDERLINE "WON'T," 'CAUSE
THAT MAKES THE COMPETITION
LOOK LIKE...
MAYBE THEY--
- I'M SERIOUS.
WE'RE NOT DOING IT.
IT'S ILLEGAL, AND, UH, IT'S ALSO
KIND OF A STUPID WAY
TO MAKE A QUICK BUCK.
- IT'S NOT STUPID.
YOU'RE STUPID.
- NICE POUT, DAD.
- I WASN'T CALLING YOU STUPID.
I WAS CALLING THE IDEA STUPID.
IF YOU'D SPEND
A LITTLE MORE TIME
LEARNING ABOUT THE BUSINESS...
AND LESS TIME WITH THE TRICKS,
YOU'D KNOW THAT.
- IF I DIDN'T HAVE A LIVE DOVE
IN MY PANTS RIGHT NOW,
I WOULD LEAP ACROSS
THIS TABLE AND--
YOU KNOW WHAT?
FORGET IT.
- LET'S GO AHEAD AND TAKE FIVE.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS FRUSTRATED,
[grunting]
AND RETURNED TO HIS OFFICE
TO FIND LINDSAY.
- GOB IS DRIVING ME CRAZY.
I FINALLY GOT RID OF HIM
FOR A LITTLE WHILE,
AND DAD PUT HIM
RIGHT BACK IN THE BUSINESS.
- YOU TWO HAVE ALWAYS FOUGHT.
I THINK I EVEN
HAVE VIDEO OF THAT.
- YOU AND HALF OF ORANGE COUNTY.
[narrator]
AS CHILDREN,
GEORGE SR. WOULD OFTEN PROVOKE
THE BOYS TO FIGHT ONE ANOTHER.
- HE'S CALLING YOU A LIAR.
- I DON'T WANT
YOUR CARDS, MICHAEL.
- HE'S LYING.
[narrator]
HE BELIEVED IT CREATED
A COMPETITIVE SPIRIT...
WHICH EQUIPPED THEM
FOR THE CHALLENGES OF LIFE.
- HEY!
LET'S KEEP IT
IN FRAME.
[narrator]
HE ALSO BELIEVED FOOTAGE
OF THE TUSSLES WOULD BE
A BIG HIT...
IN THE BURGEONING
HOME VIDEO MARKET.
HE SOON FRANCHISED THE CONCEPT
WITH SUCH TITLES AS...
BOYFIGHTS 2,
[grunting]
A BOYFIGHTS COOKOUT,
[indistinct]
AND BACKSEAT BOYFIGHTS:
THE TRIP TO UNCLE JACK'S 70th.
- HOW DO YOU THINK I FEEL?
- YOU WEREN'T EVEN
IN THE TAPES.
- I WAS TALKING
ABOUT MY MARRIAGE.
ARE WE STILL TALKING
ABOUT THE TAPES?
- APPARENTLY NOT.
WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH YOUR MARRIAGE?
- WELL, AS YOU KNOW, BOB LOBLAW
AND I HAVE HAD A SECRET
LITTLE THING GOING.
- VERY SECRET.
HE DOESN'T KNOW.
- HE HAS NOT KNOWN OF IT.
THAT'S CORRECT.
BUT LAST NIGHT HE FINALLY
RESPONDED TO ONE OF MY
LITTLE HINTS.
WHY WON'T YOU--
[bleeps] ME?
- LOOK--
I'M NOT BLIND.
YOU'RE AN ATTRACTIVE WOMAN,
AND YOU'VE BEEN DRESSING
LIKE A COMMON WHORE.
- WELL, I'VE BEEN TRYING.
- BUT YOU ASKED ME TO REPRESENT
YOU IN YOUR DIVORCE.
I CAN'T SEE A CLIENT.
- THEN RECOMMEND
SOMEBODY ELSE.
- WELL, OUR COPY BOY
IS VERY STRIKING,
BUT HE OFTEN HAS TONER
ON HIS FINGERS.
- I MEANT ANOTHER LAWYER.
- OH.
- SO NOW I HAVE TO TELL TOBIAS
WE'RE GETTING DIVORCED,
BREAK THE NEWS TO MAEBY,
PLUS FIT AN
EYEBROW PLUCK IN THERE,
ALL BEFORE THE WEEKEND.
- PERHAPS YOU CAN TALK TO MAEBY
WHILE YOU'RE GETTING
YOUR EYEBROWS PLUCKED.
IT'LL LOOK LIKE
YOUR EYES ARE WATERING
'CAUSE YOU'RE SAD.
[narrator]
LATER THAT DAY MICHAEL WENT
TO HIS PARENTS' APARTMENT...
TO TALK ABOUT THE PROBLEM
HE WAS HAVING WITH GOB.
- WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
- THEY'RE PAINTING
THE WHOLE BUILDING,
SO I'M HAVING
THE INSIDE DONE TOO.
AND THAT GOES
INTO STORAGE, RIGHT?
NOT INTO YOUR APARTMENT.
- ¿QUE?
- WHAT'S SPANISH FOR
"I KNOW YOU SPEAK ENGLISH"?
- MOM, IF YOU'RE GONNA SPEAK
TO THESE GUYS LIKE THIS,
YOU MIGHT WANT TO SLEEP
WITH ONE EYE OPEN.
- ACTUALLY, I'LL BE
SLEEPING AT YOUR PLACE.
PAINT FUMES ARE DEADLY.
- YOU KNOW DAD'S
UNDER HOUSE ARREST HERE.
- IT'LL BE NICE TO GET
A BREAK FROM HIM TOO.
BESIDES, I CERTAINLY
CAN'T RECUPERATE HERE.
- RECUPERATE?
- I DIDN'T WANT TO WORRY ANYONE.
IT'S A ROUTINE PROCEDURE--
VERY COMMON FOR WOMEN MY AGE.
- I SEE.
THE APARTMENT'S NOT THE ONLY
THING GETTING A FACE LIFT, HUH?
HOPE YOU KEPT YOUR PUNCH CARDS.
YOU'RE ABOUT DUE
FOR A FREE ONE.
- WE HAVE TO PAY
FOR THE PAINT.
- NO, NO, NO.
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING A CENTAVO
UNTIL YOU FINISH ALL THE WORK.
- YOU GUYS ARE BOTH GONNA BE
SLEEPING WITH YOUR EYES OPEN.
MOM, HOWEVER,
WILL NOT HAVE A CHOICE.
DAD, NEED YOU TO HELP ME
GET RID OF GOB.
- THAT SHIP SAILED 35 YEARS AGO.
- DOESN'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THE BUSINESS.
TODAY HE SUGGESTED
THAT WE DO AN ILLEGAL
COLOMBIAN DEAL.
- YOU SAID THAT WAS LEGAL.
- THAT WAS YOUR IDEA?
- I MAY HAVE MENTIONED IT.
- YOU TOLD GOB TO DO IT,
DIDN'T YOU?
DID YOU JUST WANT TO GET US AT
EACH OTHER'S THROATS AGAIN,
LIKE YOU USED TO DO
WITH THE BOYFIGHTS VIDEOS?
- BOYFIGHTS?
- LUCHAS DE MUCHACHOS.
- OH, SI
LUCHAS DE MUCHACHOS.
- WE HAD THIS VIDEO.
- SI
[narrator]
THE TAPES WERE A BIG HIT
IN LATIN AMERICA.
- DON'T LOOK AT ME.
I HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH THEM--
EXCEPT FOR SOME
OF THE BABY BUSTER SHORTS.
- MAYBE I WAS TRYING
TO TEACH YOU SOMETHING.
MAYBE I WAS TRYING
TO TEACH YOU HOW TO COMPETE.
I DIDN'T DO IT WITH BUSTER,
AND LOOK HOW HE TURNED OUT.
- IS BUSTER.
- BABY BUSTER.
- "YO QUIERO LECHE.
YO QUIERO LECHE DE MADRE."
EVEN THOUGH I AM SO OLD.
[laughing]
- THOSE TAPES MADE QUITE AN
IMPRESSION ON THESE PAINTERS.
- I THINK I TURNED OUT
PRETTY DARN WELL, MYSELF.
- OH, YOU JUST TURNED OUT GREAT.
I USED MY CONTACTS TO
GET YOU A JOB, AND YOU QUIT.
[narrator]
THE JOB WAS AT
AN IRAQI-OWNED TOY STORE,
THAT WAS HOPING
TO DETER SHOPLIFTING.
- OKAY, I'LL JUST TAKE OFF
THIS CHEAP FAKE HAND,
AND WE GONNA PUT ON
THIS SIGN.
BEAUTIFUL.
YOU LIKE?
- THEY ONLY WANTED ME
BECAUSE I HAD ONE HAND--
AND I WON'T DO IT!
THAT'S NOT THE WAY MOTHER
IS RAISING ME.
- LIKE I WON'T COMPETE...
WITH MY OLDER BROTHER ANYMORE,
DESPITE THE WAY FATHER
RAISED ME.
WE'LL SHOW YOU.
- JUST LIKE I SHOWED
MR. AL-JIBAALY MUHAMMED A-ABAT.
I STOLE THIS SIGN.
OF COURSE, I LEFT
MY HAND THERE ALSO.
[narrator]
BUT FAO AL-JIBAALY
MUHAMMED A-ABAT...
WASN'T THE ONLY ONE
HAVING TROUBLE SCARING KIDS.
SO WAS HOLLYWOOD'S
THIRD-YOUNGEST
MOVIE STUDIO EXECUTIVE,
MAEBY FUNKE
[woman on screen]
THE CREATURE'S IN
YOUR IMAGINATION.
[screams]
[laughter]
- THAT'S THE BLOODSUCKER?
IT LOOKS LIKE ALF.
YOU GOT A WEEK TO FIX IT.
[man on screen]
THIS MUST BE THE CREATURE
THAT ATE OUR CAT.
[laughter]
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL MET UP WITH GOB.
- HEY, GOB.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
THAT COLOMBIAN THING
WAS DAD'S IDEA?
- WELL, DAD SAID NOT TO BECAUSE
YOU DON'T THINK I'M SMART,
AND THAT I SHOULD
TAKE CREDIT FOR IT.
IT WAS JUST DAD...
TRYING TO TURN US AGAINST EACH
OTHER AGAIN, AND OF COURSE
I THINK YOU'RE SMART.
OKAY? HEY, WHAT'S
GOING ON DOWN THERE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- YOU DON'T WANT A HUNGRY DOVE
DOWN YOUR PANTS.
THAT'S HOW TONY WONDER
LOST A NUT.
LOOK, I KNOW THAT I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THIS HOUSING STUFF,
BUT I'VE GOT THIS
CHRISTIAN GIRLFRIEND NOW,
AND SHE'S TRYING TO GET ME
TO BE A BETTER MAN...
AND RECONNECT WITH MY SON,
AND I'M TRYING TO GET HER
TO RENOUNCE GOD
AND-- [bleep] ME,
AND I JUST WANT TO PROVE TO HER
THAT I'M WORTH IT.
- AS ALWAYS, GOB,
A MIXED BAG THERE,
BUT THE MIDDLE PART SOUNDED
PRETTY ADMIRABLE FOR A SECOND,
SO HERE'S WHAT I WANT TO DO.
I WANT TO GET YOU YOUR OWN
BANANA STAND FRANCHISE,
AND YOU CAN HAVE STEVE
WORK AT IT.
- YOU'D DO THAT FOR ME?
- YES. YEAH. YOU CAN
DESIGN YOUR OWN SHACK.
- AND CHOOSE MY OWN LOCATION?
- WHATEVER YOU WANT.
YOU'RE GONNA BE 100%
IN CHARGE, ALL RIGHT?
BUT THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
IS THAT WE NEVER LET DAD...
TURN US AGAINST
EACH OTHER AGAIN.
- THANKS, MICHAEL.
HMM.
IF YOU FEEL SOMETHING
MOVING DOWN THERE,
IT'S JUST THE BIRD.
- I KNOW IT.
[dove cooing]
[narrator]
AND A FEW DAYS LATER,
[ringing]
MICHAEL GOT A CALL
FROM HIS SON.
- HEY, DAD, DID YOU KNOW
GOB STARTED A BANANA STAND?
- YEAH, THAT WAS MY IDEA.
I'M TRYING TO GET US
TO BE LESS COMPETITIVE.
- THAT'S GONNA BE DIFFICULT.
PLUS THEY HAVE
A VERY AGGRESSIVE SLOGAN.
[narrator]
GOB HAD OPENED A NEW
FROZEN BANANA STAND, LIKE,
TWENTY FEET FROM THE OLD
FROZEN BANANA STAND.
- WHAT'S GOING ON?
YOU JUST THOUGHT YOU'D
PUT THE STAND RIGHT HERE?
- DID THE RESEARCH.
DO YOU KNOW THAT MORE
FROZEN BANANAS ARE SOLD...
RIGHT HERE ON THIS BOARDWALK
THAN ANYWHERE IN THE O.C.?
- DON'T CALL IT THAT.
- ALSO GONNA NEED A CHECK,
'CAUSE I KIND OF WENT...
OUT OF POCKET ON THE NEW SIGN--
AND I NEED SOME BANANAS
AND SOME CHOCOLATE...
FROM THE OTHER BRANCH.
- JUST TAKE THE SIGN DOWN--
TAKE THE WHOLE BOOTH DOWN.
YOU'RE CANNIBALIZING
OUR BUSINESS.
- YOU'RE JUST SCARED
OF A LITTLE "COMPETISH."
- YOU GUYS DON'T EVEN
HAVE BANANAS, SO I'M
NOT TOO WORRIED.-
IN FACT, YOU KNOW WHAT?
ME AND MY SON ARE GONNA
KICK YOUR LITTLE SHACK'S ASS.
- DAD, IT'S OKAY.
WE CAN JUST WORK
TOGETHER WITH THEM, YOU KNOW?
- THAT MAKES SENSE.
I MEAN, WE DON'T REALLY
EVEN KNOW THE RECIPE.
- YOU JUST FREEZE THE BANANA,
AND THEN YOU STICK IT--
- DON'T TELL 'EM.
- STICK IT IN THE WHAT?
- NO, IT'S OKAY.
WE'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
AND WHEN WE DO,
WE'LL HAVE THE LAST LAUGH.
WE'LL BE THE LAUGHINGSTOCK
OF THE BOARDWALK.
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY WAS PREPARING
FOR HER OWN COMPETITION.
- THIS IS TREAT.
HE'LL BE REPRESENTING YOU.
HE STARTED OFF AS MY PARALEGAL,
BUT HE'S A LAWYER NOW.
- WELL, AS OF NEXT MONDAY.
- WELL, WE'LL FUDGE THAT.
LINDSAY, JUST DO ME
ONE FAVOR.
DON'T MENTION ME BY NAME
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT
YOUR FUTURE PLANS FOR DATING.
IT REFLECTS POORLY ON ME.
- RIGHT, RIGHT.
THE CONFLICT OF INTEREST.
- YEAH, THAT TOO.
- HELLO, LINDSAY.
- TOBIAS. DID YOU GET A LAWYER?
ONLY THE BEST-LOOKING
AND BEST-EDUCATED LAWYER
IN THE WHOLE O.C.
- DON'T CALL IT THAT.
- OKAY.
- BOB LOBLAW. HOW ARE YOU?
- BOB'S REPRESENTING YOU?
[narrator]
HE WAS.
ONE DAY EARLIER,
TOBIAS HAD SPOKEN TO HIM...
ON THE PHONE.
- WHETHER OR NOT THOSE
PROMISES WERE MADE EXPLICIT.
- YOU... WANT ME
TO BE EXPLICIT?
ANYWAY, AS IT TURNS OUT,
BOB WAS OFFERING
TO BE MY LAWYER.
[chuckles]
[narrator]
AND THAT NIGHT,
BUSTER ARRIVED
WITH A POST-OP LUCILLE.
- THERE SHE IS.
- [muffled]
- SHE WANTS TO KNOW
WHERE YOU WANT TO PUT HER.
- SHE CAN TAKE MY ROOM.
- [muffled]
- SHE WANTS TO KNOW
IF I CAN SLEEP THERE TOO.
- [ frantic mumbling ]
- SHE SAID THAT'S VERY
IMPORTANT TO HER.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL MEET YOU
UP THERE, MOTHER.
- [muffled]
- YOU BETTER NOT LOCK IT!
I'LL KICK IT IN!
OH, BY THE WAY.
DOCTOR SAID NO KISSING HER
ON THE FACE FOR ONE WEEK.
I WAS LIKE,
"MAKE IT TWO WEEKS.
SEE IF I CARE."
[laughs]
- GOT A NEW HAND?
- OH, YEAH.
I'M TRYING IT OUT.
GUESS WHO I RAN INTO
AT THE PROSTHETIC SHOP
WHILE I WAS WAITING FOR MOTHER.
[man]
SORRY, NO REFUNDS--
AND THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T TAKE
YOUR FOOT OUT OF ITS WRAPPER.
- J. WALTER WEATHERMAN.
YOU'RE THE MAN WHO USED
TO SCARE US AS CHILDREN,
AND ONE TIME AS AN ADULT.
[narrator]
GEORGE SR.
HAD ALWAYS USED HIM...
TO TEACH HIS CHILDREN
LASTING LESSONS.
THEY USUALLY INVOLVED
HIS PROSTHETIC ARM
BEING RIPPED OFF.
[screaming]
- AND THAT'S WHY YOU ALWAYS
LEAVE A NOTE.
YOU'RE ONE
OF GEORGE BLUTH'S KIDS.
- UH-HUH.
- I GUESS YOU'LL BE
SCARING CHILDREN YOURSELF NOW.
- AS A MATTER OF FACT, I WON'T.
IF ANYTHING, IT
STRENGTHENED MY RESOLVE...
TO BE MORE THAN JUST
A ONE-ARMED MAN--
EVEN IF IT MEANS ME NEVER
TAKING A JOB AGAIN.
[phone rings]
- ALMOST MAKES IT WORTH IT.
HELLO.
- LISTEN. I HEARD...
THAT YOU GAVE GOB
A BANANA STAND.
THEY DID GREAT.
HE AND STEVE TOOK IN
OVER $700.
- THEY DID?
- YEAH.
SO I GUESS THE BLUTH COMPANY'S
GOT A NEW HEIR.
[narrator]
THAT'S WHEN MICHAEL REALIZED
IT WAS TIME TO GET SERIOUS.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
THE BANANA SUIT IS?
[narrator]
THAT NIGHT, MAEBY,
DISPLACED BY BUSTER,
HEARD A NOISE.
[liquid pouring]
- HELLO? GEORGE MICHAEL?
- [hissing]
I'M THIRSTY.
- [screaming]
[narrator]
AND MAEBY KNEW SHE HAD FOUND
HER BLOODSUCKING CREATURE.
THE NEXT DAY, MICHAEL TOOK OFF
WORK TO MAN THE BANANA STAND,
WHILE HIS SON
MANNED A BANANA.
- HOW YOU DOIN' THERE, CHAMP?
- IS MY NAME CHAMP?
IT'S SO HOT.
- WHY DON'T YOU TAKE FIVE?
- THAT'S NOT INCLUDING
THE FIVE MINUTES IT TAKES
TO GET OUT OF THIS THING?
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING
OUT OF IT.
- ATTENTION, EVERYONE.
WHY GO TO A BANANA STAND
WHEN WE CAN MAKE
YOUR BANANA STAND?
I GIVE YOU BARBARA
AND DEE.
[smooth jazz]
DON'T WORRY.
THESE YOUNG BEAUTIES HAVE
BEEN NOWHERE NEAR THE BANANAS.
- DAD, ARE THEY STRIPPERS?
- IF I KNOW YOUR UNCLE,
THEY'RE AT LEAST STRIPPERS.
I GUESS WE GOTTA UP THE ANTE.
- NO, DAD.
THEN THEY'RE
JUST GONNA UP IT, AND IT'LL
GO BACK AND FORTH ALL DAY.
- IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES,
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO.
[narrator]
AND THEY DID--
BUT IT WAS LESS ENTERTAINING
THAN YOU MIGHT IMAGINE--
NO MATTER WHAT MUSIC
WAS PUT UNDER IT.
[man singing in spanish]
[r&amp;b]
[folk-rock]
[jazz]
[pop]
[r&amp;b]
[narrator]
IT WAS KIND OF FUNNY
TO "YELLOW SUBMARINE,"
BUT WHO COULD AFFORD IT?
[camera shutter clicking]
SO HERE'S WHAT HAPPENED
AT THE END.
- HEY, STOP FIGHTING!
STOP IT!
- THAT'S IT.
THEY'RE RIGHT, OKAY?
THIS IS INSANE.
WE'RE JUST "BOYFIGHTING" AGAIN.
- AND FOR WHAT?
A HEFTY BAG FULL OF PESOS.
- YOU'VE BEEN TAKING PESOS?
- DAD SAID I SHOULD.
- DAD'S INVOLVED WITH THIS?
- WELL, HE CHOSE THE LOCATION--
AND THE STRIPPERS AND THE SIGN.
EVERY PART OF IT, REALLY.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
DON'T YOU SEE
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE?
DAD'S CLEARLY GOING AHEAD
WITH THE COLOMBIAN DEAL,
AND HE'S LAUNDERING IT
THROUGH YOUR BANANA SHACK.
HE PITTED US AGAINST EACH OTHER
SO I'D BE TOO BUSY TO NOTICE.
WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK IT'S TIME FOR US
TO TEACH DAD A LESSON.
- GET THE PERSON WHO
TERRORIZED US THE MOST
IN OUR CHILDHOOD.
- SHE'S STILL HEALING.
LET'S GET J. WALTER WEATHERMAN.
[narrator]
MICHAEL AND GOB HAD DECIDED...
TO TEACH THEIR FATHER
A LESSON.
- WE NEED THE NUMBER
OF THE ONE-ARMED MAN.
- I'M NOT GIVING YOU THAT.
YOU WANT TO USE HIS
DISABILITY TO SCARE SOMEONE.
THAT'S EVERYTHING I'M AGAINST.
READ THE BUTTON, MISTER!
- "THE ONLY SCARY THING
ABOUT...
A ONE-ARMED MAN
TRYING TO SCARE SOMEONE
IS THE FACT THAT"--
- THAT HE FEELS THAT HIS
ONE ARM IS GOOD FOR NOTHING
BUT TRYING TO SCARE SOMEBODY.
- IT'S UPSIDE DOWN.
- LET'S SEE YOU TRY
TO PUT A BUTTON ON...
WITH THIS.
- [screams]
- STOP SCREAMING.
IT'S NOT SCARY.
- I'M GONNA
GET THE NUMBER MYSELF,
'CAUSE WE'RE NOT GONNA...
GO THROUGH OUR LIVES
BEING CONTROLLED BY THIS GUY.
WHAT IS MORE PATHETIC
THAN GROWN MEN BEING
SCARED OF THEIR FATHER?
- I'M THIRSTY.
[screaming]
- OH, MY GOD!
[narrator]
THIS CONTINUED FOR A WHILE.
AND LATER, MICHAEL AND GOB
WENT TO PUT THEIR PLAN
IN ACTION.
- I GAVE THE COLOMBIANS
BACK THEIR MONEY,
AND I TOLD THEM...
THAT YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO MAKE THE DEAL.
I HAVE TO WARN YOU, THOUGH,
THEY DIDN'T SOUND
TOO HAPPY.
- LET'S JUST HOPE THEY
DON'T TRY TO GET EVEN BY
"CIR-SUM-VENTING" THE LAW.
- WHAT IS THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- KIDNAP OR-- MICHAEL SAID IT.
- WHAT, ARE YOU KIDDING?
I HAVE AN ANKLE MONITOR.
I CAN'T EVEN GO INTO THE HALLWAY
WITHOUT THE COPS COMING UP.
STOP IT!
- CLEARLY YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THERE'S AN OFF CHANCE
THEY MIGHT JUST WANT TO
TAKE YOU, LEAVE THE ANKLE.
BUT ANYHOW--
STALL HIM.
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL WENT TO SOLICIT
HELP FOR THE LESSON.
- HOW WOULD YOU AND SOME OF
YOUR FRIENDS LIKE TO HELP US...
TEACH MR. BLUTH A LESSON?
MAYBE POSE AS COLOMBIANS.
- BUT WE ARE GUATEMALAN.
WON'T HE KNOW
THE DIFFERENCE?
- I THINK ANYTHING SOUTH
OF SAN DIEGO WILL BE JUST FINE.
- ORLANDO WAS
IN THE GROUNDLINGS.
- JUST CLASSES.
IS IT GOING TO BE UNSCRIPTED,
LIKE CURB?
[narrator]
GEORGE SR., MEANWHILE, HAD
GROWN SUSPICIOUS OF HIS SONS.
- WHAT WAS THAT
WITH MICHAEL JUST NOW?
- HE WANTS TO TEACH YOU
A LESSON.
- WHAT KIND OF LESSON?
- J. WALTER WEATHERMAN LESSON.
HE'S GONNA FAKE YOUR KIDNAPPING
AND HELICOPTER RIDE TO COLOMBIA.
- HE'S GONNA TEACH ME A LESSON
USING MY OWN SCARE TOY?
- WEATHERMAN WOULDN'T DO IT.
I THINK BUSTER TURNED HIM.
- YEAH, WELL,
HE'LL SAY YES FOR ME.
WE'LL GO ALONG WITH HIS LESSON,
BUT WE'RE GONNA TEACH HIM
ONE OF OUR OWN--
BUT IT'S GOTTA
BE A SECRET, OKAY?
BETWEEN A DAD AND HIS--
HIS FAVORITE SON.
- DON'T WORRY, POP.
GOB BLUTH DOESN'T CAVE.
- YEAH, YOU JUST DID FOR ME.
- WELL, YOU ASKED ME TO
SO I THOUGHT--
- OKAY, GO, GO, GO. IT'S FINE.
[narrator]
AND LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
WERE BACK WITH THE ARBITRATOR.
- AS YOU KNOW, IT IS VERY
DIFFICULT...
TO ESTABLISH
FAULT IN A DIVORCE,
BUT ONE INDICATOR IS FIDELITY.
MY CLIENT HAS NOT PURSUED SEX
OUTSIDE OF THIS MARRIAGE.
- NOR IN IT.
- I GOT THIS ONE.
CAN THE SAME
BE SAID FOR YOU?
- OH, ABSOLUTELY.
I'VE DONE EVERYTHING
TO MAKE THIS MARRIAGE WORK.
- THAT'S INTERESTING.
CAN YOU TELL ME WHAT YOUR
PLANS ARE FOR THIS EVENING?
- UH, I HAVE PLANS
WITH A FRIEND.
- A MAN?
WHAT'S HIS NAME, PLEASE?
- DON'T ANSWER THAT.
- I WITHDRAW THE QUESTION.
WHY DON'T WE STOP FOR THE DAY?
SO MRS. FUNKE...
CAN GET TO HER DATE
WITH HER MYSTERIOUS...
MR. BLAH-BLAH-BLAH.
AT 8:30, UNLESS YOU WANT
TO SIT AT THE BAR.
[narrator]
IT WAS THE FIRST TIME
SOMEONE TOOK TOBIAS'S SIDE,
AND HE WANTED TO THANK HIM.
- AS MUCH AS I HATE LOSING
LINDSAY AND EVERYTHING,
I FEEL LIKE I'M MAKING
A FRIEND IN YOU,
SO I WAS WONDERING IF MAYBE
TONIGHT YOU JUST WANT TO...
TAKE IN A MOVIE...
OR A SCHVITZ...
OR JUST STAY IN AND NEST.
- ACTUALLY, I WAS GOING
TO STAY IN MY OFFICE TONIGHT
AND WORK ON MY LAW BLOG.
- OF COURSE--
THE BOB LOBLAW LAW BLOG.
[chuckles]
WOW. YOU, SIR, ARE A MOUTHFUL.
[narrator]
WHILE TOBIAS
WAS TRYING TO GET HIS MOUTH
AROUND BOB LOBLAW,
MAEBY WAS SHOWING MORT MEYERS
A MONSTER OF HER OWN.
- [groans]
OH, THAT'S TERRIFYING.
WHO DID THAT FOR YOU,
INDUSTRIAL LIGHT
&amp; MAGIC?
- TOPELSON PLASTIC AND SILICONE.
- DID HE DO LAND OF THE DEAD?
- YEAH. HE'S BEEN
IN BEVERLY HILLS FOR YEARS.
- GET OUR MAKEUP PEOPLE ON IT.
[narrator]
AND GEORGE SR. WAITED...
FOR THE FAKE KIDNAPPING HE KNEW
MICHAEL HAD ORCHESTRATED.
[grunting]
- DON'T MOVE!
- HEY, WELL, LET'S DO IT.
- GET INTO THE BOX,
OLD MAN.
- OH, BLANKETS. THAT'S--
WHO THOUGHT OF THAT?
THAT IS VERY NICE.
- COME ON,
GET IN THE TRUNK!
- WHAT ABOUT--
WHAT ABOUT MY ANKLE MONITOR?
- WE HAVE AN ANKLE MONITOR
DEACTIVATOR.
[beeping]
OH, GOOD. SEE, I'VE BEEN
MEANING TO GET ONE OF THOSE.
I'M NOT GONNA RESIST YOU GUYS
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW,
I DON'T WANT YOU TO BEAT ME.
[narrator]
BUT THE MISTREATED PAINTERS...
WERE ACTUALLY LOOKING FORWARD
TO THAT PART.
- OH! FORGOT MY iPOD.
[groans]
[cheering]
- START THE HELICOPTER!
[narrator]
AND SO MICHAEL,
BELIEVING HIMSELF...
TO BE AIDED BY GOB,
SET TO WORK.
BUT THIS TOO PRODUCED
LESS-THAN-COMPELLING FOOTAGE.
[man singing]
IN A YELLOW BOAT
A YELLOW BOAT
WE'RE MAKIN' A STAND
IN A YELLOW BOAT
[narrator]
AND THIS IS HOW THAT ENDED.
- PUT ON THE SOUND EFFECTS.
PUT ON THE SOUND EFFECTS.
[Franklin singing]
- CD-- CD ONE. CD ONE.
[train whistle blowing]
- TRACK TWO. TRACK TWO.
[jungle sound effects]
- PUT THE HOSTAGE HERE
BY THE OTTOMAN.
- GET IT OUT OF HERE.
WHAT'S IT DOING IN HERE?
OTTOMAN OUT.
[narrator]
AND GEORGE SR. WAS RELEASED...
FROM HIS LONG JOURNEY
INTO THE LIVING ROOM.
- WHERE AM I?
- COLOMBIA.
WHERE DO YOU THINK?
- AND YOU JUST MISSED
THE LAST TRAIN...
THAT WILL COME THROUGH
THE JUNGLE FOR THREE DAYS.
- HE'S GOOD.
- HE'S A GROUNDLING.
- YOU HAVE BETRAYED US,
AND WE WILL MAKE YOU PAY,
AND THEN WE WILL GO BACK
FOR YOUR SONS.
- MY SONS?
NO.
- THEY TOO WILL SUFFER
FOR YOUR TERRIBLE DECISIONS.
- AND YOU SHOULD REALLY PAY YOUR
WORKERS WHAT THEY DESERVE--
NOT MAKE THEM HAVE TO BUY
THEIR OWN SUPPLIES.
- NOT JUST THE PAINTING.
THE SANDING TOO.
- YEAH, AND THE TAPING
IS VERY TIME-CONSUMING.
[narrator]
MICHAEL DECIDED HIS FATHER
WAS READY TO LEARN HIS LESSON.
- AND THAT IS WHY--
- HE'S GOT A GUN!
- I CAN'T LET YOU DO IT!
GET AWAY!
[gunshot]
GET AWAY. I'LL SHOOT.
I WILL, I WILL.
I'LL TAKE YOU ALL OUT.
- THIS IS ALL FAKE.
THESE GUYS ARE PAINTERS.
- I WILL, I WILL!
- OH, GOD! MY ARM.
- DAD, YOU JUST SHOT OFF
THIS GUY--
THIS GUY'S ARM.
- AND THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T
TEACH YOUR FATHER A LESSON.
- WHO'S THE STUPID ONE NOW?
THANK YOU, GOB.
- GOB? YOU TOLD HIM?
I THOUGHT WE
WERE A TEAM.
- IT'S NOT FUN
FEELING STUPID, IS IT?
- YOU SON OF A--
[both shouting, grunting]
- WAIT A MINUTE.
I GOTTA GET MY CAMERA.
- GET OFF OF ME!
- WHAT IS ALL THIS?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- KEEP IT IN FRAME.
YOU WANNA-- CHIN OUT.
- I WILL KILL YOU!
- I'M GONNA KILL YOU.
- YOU'RE GOING OUT OF FRAME.
- I'LL KILL YOU.
- [screams]
- NO!
- OH, MY GOD! MICHAEL!
[panting]
DAD-- IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I'M SORRY.
- AND THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T
PIT GOB AND ME AGAINST
EACH OTHER.
- YES! YEAH!
- GOB.
- YOU SET ME UP.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- NO MORE "BOYFIGHTS."
- J. WALTER WEATHERMAN
WAS IN ON IT TOO?
- RIGHT FROM THE VERY START.
- SO YOU DID USE HIM.
LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
LOOK AT MY HOME.
- FREEZE! DROP THE GUN.
- IT'S OKAY. WE'RE JUST TRYING
TO TEACH THIS GUY A LESSON.
- DROP THE GUN!
- [screaming]
OH, MY GOOD HAND!
BUSTER'S GOOD HAND
JUST CAME...
FLYING OFF.
- AND THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T
USE A ONE-ARMED PERSON
TO SCARE SOMEONE.
[narrator]
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MAEBY FINDS A WAY
TO SCARE AN ENTIRE GENERATION.
[announcer]
THIS CHRISTMAS,
TERROR HAS A NEW FACE.
- [guttural voice]
I'M THIRSTY.
[screaming]
[announcer]
GANGY.
- WE SHOULD START PRODUCTION
ON GANGY TWO.
- WELL, I KNOW SHE
WANTED A SKIN PEEL.
[man singing]
I THINK BACK
TO MY DAYS IN SCHOOL
NOW I SEE I WAS SUCH A FOOL
YELLOW IS JUST
ANOTHER SHADE OF BLUE
WE'RE FLOATING ALONG
WE'RE FLOATING ALONG..
IN A YELLOW BOAT
A YELLOW BOAT
IN A YELLOW BOAT.
WE'RE MAKING A STAND
WE'RE TAKING A STAND--
IN A YELLOW BOAT
A YELLOW BOAT
A YELLOW BOAT.