announcer: TONIGHT, AN ARRESTED
DEVELOPMENT YOU CAN'T MISS.
A CAVALCADE OF STARS.
THE SHOCKING FINAL MOMENTS
WILL BE PRESENTED LIVE.
AND ONE OF THESE PEOPLE...
WILL DIE.
narrator:
THE BLUTHS WERE DESPERATE.
- I ASSUME YOU'VE SEEN THIS.
THE PRESS HAD THEM
ALL BUT FINISHED.
- WHAT?
WHAT IS IT?
- THIS ISN'T GONNA WORK
OVER THE PHONE, DAD.
- THEN GET BOB LOBLAW TO HIRE ME
ANOTHER SURROGATE.
- THAT'S KIND OF THE POINT.
MR. LOBLAW NO LONGER
WORKS FOR US...
BECAUSE SOMEONE
WANTED A BOYFRIEND.
- WELL, DON'T BLAME ME.
- I WAS TALKING TO LINDSAY,
ACTUALLY.
BUT HE WAS CLEARLY TURNED OFF
TO THE BOTH OF YOU.
NOW, WE'RE GONNA NEED A NEW
LAWYER.
AND THAT IS GOING TO
MEAN ABOUT A $100,000 RETAINER.
IF WE WANT A CHANCE
OF KEEPING THIS FAMILY GOING
PAST THE NEXT FEW WEEKS,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO PULL OUT
ALL THE STOPS.
WHAT AM I TALKING ABOUT?
I'M TALKING ABOUT ALL OF YOU
GETTING JOBS.
- THE BEST PLACE TO LOOK FOR A
JOB--
- EW!
- WHO THREW THE TOMATO?
- HOW THE HELL ARE WE
GONNA GET A HUNDRED GRAND?
- WELL, I KNOW THIS ISN'T
EXACTLY WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR,
BUT MAEBY WAS JUST ACCEPTED
INTO PRIVATE SCHOOL.
I'VE SENT THE CHECK IN ALREADY.
- NO, THAT'S NOT WHAT
I'M LOOKIN' FOR AT ALL.
- MICHAEL, IT'S THE MOST
PRESTIGIOUS
PRIVATE SCHOOL IN TOWN.
- OH, NO.
NOT THE MILFORD ACADEMY.
narrator: CHILDREN WERE NEITHER
TO BE SEEN NOR HEARD...
AT THE SCHOOL BUSTER
HAD ATTENDED.
- IT'S THE EXACT OPPOSITE.
IT'S CALLED "OPENINGS."
- OH, GREAT.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE ANOTHER ONE OF
THOSE GRADELESS, STRUCTURELESS,
NEW AGE "FEEL-GOODERIES."
- THEY TEACH SELF-EXPRESSION
AND GETTING IN TOUCH
WITH FEELINGS, MICHAEL.
I MEAN, I KNOW
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY.
- THE BOY WHO COULDN'T CRY.
- HE'S A ROBOT!
- OH, MICHAEL CAN CRY.
HE JUST DOESN'T WANNA RUST.
- YES, HE'S LIKE THE STEEL MAN
FROM THE WIZARD OF OZ.
- TIN MAN?
- IS THAT WHAT HE'S CALLED?
- HE KNOWS.
- YOU KNOW, LINDSAY, SINCE YOU
SENT THE CHECK,
THIS IS HOW
YOU'RE GONNA PAY FOR IT.
YOU'RE GONNA BE IN CHARGE
OF THE HOUSE FROM NOW ON.
OKAY?  THE COOKING,
CLEANING, ALL OF IT.
- YOU'RE GOING TO PUT LINDSAY
IN CHARGE OF THE COOKING?
AT LEAST YOU'LL LOSE WEIGHT.
- YOU KNOW, MOM,
I THINK THE ONLY
TIME YOU EVER COOKED FOR US
WAS THE MORNING ROSA'S MOM DIED.
- YOU GAVE US CEREAL
IN AN ASHTRAY.
- GOB, PAL? HOW ABOUT YOU?
CAN YOU FIND SOME WORK?
- OH, SURE, MICHAEL.
AS WHAT?
A WAITER?
CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING,
MADAM?
- [laughing]
- [George laughs]
- I WILL HAVE A VODKA, THOUGH.
- WHAT? OH.
- YOU KNOW, IF YOU'D EVER
ACCIDENTALLY
WORKED A DAY IN YOUR LIFE,
YOU'D KNOW THERE'S NO
INDIGNITY IN IT.
- GREAT.
SHE'LL HAVE A VODKA.
- INSTEAD OF SELLING OUT,
BECOMING HOUSEWIVES AND WAITERS,
WHY DON'T WE HAVE
A BIG EVENT?
SOME SORT OF "SAVE OUR BLUTHS"
TYPE THING.
WE'LL THROW A LEGAL DEFENSE FUND
DINNER. ASK FOR DONATIONS.
- AS LONG AS WE DON'T
LOOK DESPERATE.
WE WANT 'EM TO THINK WE'LL TAKE
THEIR HELP, BUT DON'T NEED IT.
I SHOULD BE SEEN
A LOT AT THE CLUB.
- YEAH, OUR BACKS ARE
AGAINST THE WALL,
AND IT'S
JUST HARD TO ACCEPT...
THAT IT'S REALLY
COME TO BEGGING.
- SOMETIMES IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO STAY IN THE GAME.
narrator: PLEASE TELL YOUR
FRIENDS ABOUT THIS SHOW.
[whistling]
narrator:
MICHAEL HAD ASKED LINDSAY
TO TAKE CARE OF THE HOUSE.
AND TO HIS SURPRISE,
SHE WAS SORT OF DOING IT.
- YOU'RE SORT OF DOING IT.
- YEAH, CHECK IT OUT.
I FOUND THAT CANNED HAM
THAT WE'D HAD FOREVER,
AND I PUT IT IN A POT
OF BOILING WATER.
AND GUESS WHAT I'M CALLING IT?
- SOUP?
- HOT HAM WATER.
YOU KNOW, I'M ACTUALLY
A REALLY GOOD MOM.
I THINK IT'S 'CAUSE
MAEBY'S NEVER AROUND.
YOU SHOULD SEND GEORGE MICHAEL
TO "OPENINGS" TOO.
- YES, IT COULD HELP HIM
EXPRESS HIS FEELINGS.
- MY SON EXPRESSES HIMSELF
JUST FINE.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT, SON?
- WHAT?
YEAH, IT'S FINE.
YEAH, I GUESS.
I DON'T CARE. STOP.
- YES. HE'S A REGULAR
FREDDY WILSON, THAT ONE.
- I DON'T KNOW THAT REFERENCE.
- NO, I DON'T EITHER.
- OH, I DON'T KNOW EITHER.
- narrator: IT'S THIS GUY.
- MY SON'S FINE WHERE HE IS.
HE'S GOT THE S.A.T.'S COMING UP.
YOU GOTTA DO WELL ON THOSE.
YOU STUDYING UPSTAIRS?
- YEAH, I'M TAKING A THREE REAL
QUICK SO I CAN GET A CREAM SODA.
- OH, I'LL GET THAT FOR YOU.
- NO, I WILL GET IT.
I HAVE TO GET IT MYSELF.
JUST RELAX.
JUST CHECK THE STOVE
REAL QUICK.
- YOU KNOW, MICHAEL,
IF I MAY TAKE OFF MY ACTING
PANTS FOR A MOMENT...
AND PULL MY "ANALRAPIST"
STOCKING OVER MY HEAD,
GEORGE MICHAEL HAS BEEN
ACTING STRANGE LATELY.
I THINK HE MAY HAVE DEVELOPED
WHAT WE IN THE SOFT SCIENCES..
REFER TO AS OBSESSIVE-COMPULSIVE
DISORDER...
OR THE O.C. DISORDER.
- DON'T CALL IT THAT.
- I THINK ULTIMATELY IT'S
BECAUSE
HE'S AFRAID TO EXPRESS HIMSELF.
narrator: ACTUALLY,
IT WAS BECAUSE
HE WAS
AFRAID HIS AUNT LINDSAY
WAS GOING TO BURN
THE HOUSE DOWN.
- HI.
HOW ARE YOU?
CREAM SODA.
MAYBE HE DOES NEED THIS SCHOOL.
DID YOU SEE THIS LETTER?
YOU KNOW, IT'S DONE
WONDERS FOR MAEBY.
- "MAEBY IS AN EXCEPTIONAL
YOUNG LADY."
- EXCEPTIONAL.
"WE ARE SURE THAT SHE IS
DESTINED FOR GREAT THINGS."
- GREAT THINGS.
- "AND WE WISH HER LUCK
IN ALL HER"--
IT SAYS "OVER."
I'D PROBABLY HAVE TO CRACK THIS
OPEN TO BE SURE,
BUT THIS SOUNDS LIKE
AN EXPULSION LETTER.
"SHE'S NEVER
BEEN TO CLASS."
- WHAT KIND OF A BOARDING SCHOOL
WOULD LOSE TRACK OF ITS
STUDENTS?
- OPENINGS IS NOT
A BOARDING SCHOOL.
- I THOUGHT IT WAS
A BOARDING SCHOOL TOO.
narrator: ACTUALLY, MAEBY
HAD BEEN ON THE SET OF A FILM
CALLED SNOWBOARDING SCHOOL 2.
IN HER SECRET LIFE
AS A FILM EXECUTIVE.
- THERE GOES THAT
NONREFUNDABLE TUITION.
YOU KNOW IT IS THE ONE RULE
THEY DO HAVE THERE.
- SHE SHOULD BE PUNISHED
FOR THIS.
YOU KNOW, TOBIAS,
IF I CAN BECOME A MORE
TRADITIONAL MOTHER,
THEN MAYBE
YOU COULD START BEING MORE OF--
- NONTRADITIONAL MOTHER.
YES, YOU'RE RIGHT.
AFTER ALL,
I AM HER FATHER.
- THE CARS ARE STILL OFF, AND I
REWASHED ALL THE CLOTHES.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL DECIDED
THAT PERHAPS MAEBY'S TUITION
DIDN'T HAVE TO GO TO WASTE
AFTER ALL.
MEANWHILE,
LUCILLE WENT TO WORK
SOLICITING FOR
THE BLUTH FUND-RAISER.
- I MEAN, WE HAVE PLENTY OF
MONEY.
DON'T GET ME WRONG.
BUT WE CAN'T USE OUR PERSONAL
ASSETS TO DEFEND THE COMPANY.
narrator: JUST THEN, GOB ARRIVED
AND DECIDED TO HAVE A LAUGH.
- YOUR DRINK, MADAM.
[chuckles]
CAN I GET YOU ANYTHING--
- GET THAT ONE OUT OF HERE.
- AS YOU PLEASE.
narrator: BUT LUCILLE HAD NEVER
MADE EYE CONTACT WITH A WAITER.
- CAN YOU DROP
THESE OFF AT TWO?
- WHY NOT?
I'M JUST A WAITER.
[laughs]
- narrator: SO HE KEPT IT UP.
- WE'RE ALL OUT OF THE HALIBUT.
narrator: THE JOKE WAS OVER,
BUT THE LUNCH RUSH
WAS JUST BEGINNING.
- HEY, NEW GUY.
YOU WANNA SEAT TABLE FOUR?
- WHAT'LL YOU HAVE?
narrator: BACK AT THE PENTHOUSE,
HOWEVER, LUNCH WAS LONG OVERDUE.
- I DON'T SUPPOSE SHE LEFT
ANYTHING FOR ME TO EAT.
- NO, JUST A SOUP AND A HALF
SANDWICH
AND A WHOLE SANDWICH FOR ME.
- AH.
- HELLO. HEY.
SO WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH THE FUND-RAISER?
- WELL, UH, I DON'T THINK
THE HOME BUILDER'S ORGANIZATION
IS GONNA BE SUPPORTING US.
- YEAH, THE H.B.O.
IS NOT GONNA WANT US.
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
- WELL, I THINK IT'S SHOWTIME.
I THINK WE HAVE TO HAVE
A SHOW DURING DINNER.
HEY, WE COULD HAVE
SOME CELEBRITIES IN.
YOU KNOW, OSCAR WINNERS
LIKE, UH, NICOLE KIDMAN.
- I DON'T WANNA ROUND UP
A BUNCH OF FAMOUS PEOPLE
THAT HAVE NOTHING TO DO
WITH OUR FAMILY
AS SOME SORT OF CHEAP STUNT.
I MEAN, WHAT'S THAT GOT TO DO
WITH US?
- NOTHING, BUT YOU'RE GONNA
WRITE A SPEECH ABOUT ME...
SO THEY CAN SEE
HOW WONDERFUL I AM.
- I THINK WE GOT A BETTER
CHANCE AT NICOLE KIDMAN.
- OH? HUH?
- ACTUALLY, I MAY HAVE
AN IN WITH ANDY RICHTER.
- WELL, DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN GET HIM?
I'M KIDDING.
OF COURSE NOT HIM.
- HIS BROTHER DOES TEACH
GEORGE MICHAEL AT OPENINGS.
- GEORGE MICHAEL IS GOING TO
THAT NEW AGE FEEL-GOODERIE?
I DON'T THINK THAT'S
A GOOD IDEA.
THEY'RE GONNA
POISON HIM AGAINST YOU.
REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN WE SENT LINDSAY
TO THAT KIND OF SCHOOL?
ALL OF A SUDDEN I WAS
THE BAD GUY TO HER.
- AND YOU DON'T RESPECT MOM,
AND YOU DON'T RESPECT WOMEN.
- ARE YOU MARRIED?
- DAMN SCHOOL.
I SAID TO THE TEACHER--
I SAID, "YOU POISON HER,
I'LL POISON YOU."
narrator: GEORGE SR. DID MORE
THAN JUST SAY IT.
HE SENT THE MAN A BASKET
OF POISON MUFFINS.
- DO YOU KNOW THE MUFFIN MAN?
THERE'S A REWARD IF YOU DO.
THEN, WOULD YOU LIKE SOME FOAM
IN YOUR COFFEE?
IT'S CALLED A "CUPPUCCINO," AND
WAIT TILL YOU SEE WHAT IT COSTS.
- YOU CAN SAY WHAT YOU WANT
ABOUT THE MILFORD ACADEMY.
THE KIDS WHO CAME OUT OF THERE,
PREPARED FOR LIFE.
- DOES ANYONE KNOW HOW
TO EAT ONE OF THESE?
- YOU KNOW, GEORGE MICHAEL'S
GONNA BE FINE, OKAY?
I JUST WANT HIM TO KNOW
HOW TO EXPRESS HIMSELF.
- THAT DOESN'T DO ANYTHING.
narrator: HE WAS ACTUALLY HAVING
TROUBLE EXPRESSING HIMSELF.
- WHY DON'T YOU TELL THE GROUP
ABOUT YOURSELF?
- MY NAME IS
GEORGE MICHAEL BLUTH.
I AM A 16-YEAR-OLD
CAUCASIAN MALE.
MY MOM DIED.
AND I-I GUESS
THAT'S IT.
- HARDLY. SEE, IF IT WERE ME,
I WOULD SAY,
"I'M DONNIE RICHTER.
"I HAVE A BROTHER NAMED ANDY.
HE'S AN ATTENTION HOG.
"HE CAN'T SEEM TO REALLY ATTRACT
A REAL AUDIENCE,
"BUT I LOVE
THE FAT S.O.B. ANYWAY."
- I THOUGHT YOU LOOKED LIKE
THAT GUY ANDY RICHTER.
YOU GUYS
ARE IDENTICAL TWINS?
- IDENTICAL QUINTUPLETS,
ACTUALLY.
narrator:
THERE WAS ANDY THE SHOW-OFF,
DONNIE THE SENSITIVE ONE,
CHARETH THE FLIRT,
ROCKY THE RISK-TAKER
AND ANDY'S STUNT DOUBLE,
AND EMMETT WHO ASKED THAT
WE NOT SHOW HIS PICTURE,
ALTHOUGH COMPOSITE PHOTOGRAPHY
TELLS US HE'D LOOK SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
- HERE'S WHAT
I WANT YOU TO DO.
I WANT YOU
TO GO HOME TONIGHT...
AND WRITE SOMETHING ABOUT
HOW YOU REALLY FEEL.
SOMETHING CRITICAL.
BRING IT IN TOMORROW
AND READ IT FOR THE GROUP.
- UM, WILL THIS GO TOWARD
MY GRADE?
- OH, WE DON'T HAVE GRADES HERE.
A STUDENT EITHER LEARNS
AND GETS AN "L,"
OR THEY
FLUCTUATE IN THEIR LEARNING.
- AND WHAT DO WE GET
FOR THAT?
- AN "F."
- [singing]
MR. F.
narrator:
MAEBY, MEANWHILE,
WAS ABOUT TO HAVE A LEARNING
EXPERIENCE OF HER OWN.
- WELL, WELL, WELL.
I UNDERSTAND YOU'VE BEEN
HAVING TROUBLE WITH THAT
EXPENSIVE BOARDING SCHOOL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I CAN READ.
- OKAY, FIRST OF ALL, VARIETY
GOT IT WRONG, ALL RIGHT?
WE DIDN'T WANT THIS PROJECT.
IT WAS A COFINANCE WITH MIRAMAX.
AND POOF, MIRAMAX IS GONE.
WE'RE STILL ON THE HOOK.
IT TURNS OUT JAMIE KENNEDY
CAN'T EVEN SNOWBOARD.
[disco music]
- [sighs] ALL RIGHT,
I'LL LISTEN TO THIS LATER.
DON'T TELL ME WHERE YOU'VE
BEEN.
IT'LL JUST MAKE ME
WORRY MORE. BUT GUESS WHAT.
THERE'S A NEW DADDY IN TOWN.
- [singing]
THERE'S A NEW DADDY IN TOWN
- A DISCIPLINE DADDY.
- [singing] HE'S A DISCIPLINE
DADDY GONNA SPANK HIS BEHIND
- OH, IT'S, UH--
IT'S A PARENTING TAPE.
[music stops]
IF YOU WANNA SKIP SCHOOL,
THAT'S FINE.
YOU'LL JUST
COME TO WORK WITH ME.
- BUT YOU DON'T HAVE A JOB.
- ALL RIGHT. HERE.
TELL YOU WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO.
WE ARE GOING TO STUFF EACH ONE
OF THESE GIFT BAGS WITH...
A HEAD SHOT, SOME GLITTER
AND A DECORATIVE HAND SOAP.
AND WE'RE GONNA SEND 'EM TO
EVERY CASTING DIRECTOR IN TOWN.
AND DON'T FORGET
THE FUNNY NOTES.
- "I KNOW WHERE YOU LIVE.
HA, HA"?
CASTING DIRECTORS HATE THIS.
narrator:
THEY REALLY DO.
- [sighs] THE GLITTER QUEEN
STRUCK AGAIN.
NEVER HIRE TOBIAS FUNKE.
narrator:
AND BACK AT THE COUNTRY CLUB,
SOMETHING UNUSUAL HAD HAPPENED.
- OH, I DON'T HAVE ANY DRUGS
FOR SALE.
UNLESS, DID YOU EXPECT
ME TO FOLLOW YOU TO YOUR CAR?
- THEY'RE YOUR TIPS.
- TIPS.
narrator: AND GOB
REALIZED HE'D ACCIDENTALLY
WORKED A DAY IN HIS LIFE.
LINDSAY, MEANWHILE,
WAS BEING A MOTHER,
WHEN SOMEONE SHOWED UP
WHO NEEDED ONE.
- HEY.
- HOW'D YOU GET HERE?
- I WALKED.
I TRIED HITCHHIKING, BUT IT'S
HARD TO DO WITHOUT A THUMB.
I'M SO HUNGRY.
- WOULD YOU LIKE TO TRY
SOME OF THIS?
- MMM.
SO WATERY, AND YET THERE'S
A SMACK OF HAM TO IT.
- IT'S HOT HAM WATER.
- YEAH.
narrator:
UPSTAIRS, GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS STRUGGLING WITH HIS
ASSIGNMENT.
- CAN YOU THINK OF ANYTHING
CRITICAL TO SAY ABOUT MY DAD?
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
- I HAVE GLITTER IN MY LUNGS
FROM MAKING GOODY BAGS
FOR CASTING DIRECTORS.
AND HE'S GIVEN ME A HUNDRED MORE
TO DO FOR HOMEWORK.
IT'S, LIKE, "I DON'T
DO MY HOMEWORK.
"GEORGE MICHAEL
DOES MY HOMEWORK."
narrator:
AND THAT'S WHEN HE DECIDED IT
WAS TIME TO CHEAT OFF OF HER.
- YOU KNOW, IT MIGHT HELP IF
YOU EXPRESSED YOURSELF.
narrator:
IT ALSO GAVE HIM AN
OPPORTUNITY
TO SMELL HER NECK.
AND THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL DROVE TO OPENINGS
IN THE HOPES OF RECRUITING
DONNIE'S BROTHER
FOR THE FUND-RAISER,
WHEN HE NOTICED HIS SON
EXPRESSING HIMSELF RATHER WELL.
- HE PRETENDS HE'S THE GREAT
FATHER ALL OF A SUDDEN
AND ACTS LIKE HE'S ALL WORRIED
ABOUT ME.
BUT IT TURNS OUT HE
JUST DOES IT SO I CAN HELP HIM
WITH HIS JOKE OF A CAREER.
NO WONDER MOM
WANTED OUT SO BAD.
- OH, MY GOD.
narrator: GOB, MEANWHILE,
WAS SEVERAL DAYS IN TO BEING
AN ACCIDENTAL WAITER.
AND HE DISCOVERED
THAT A LITTLE FLIRTING
HELPED BRING IN THE TIPS.
- IF YOU DIDN'T HAVE
ADULT-ONSET DIABETES,
I WOULDN'T MIND
GIVING YOU A LITTLE SUGAR.
- OH, GOB. YOU COULD CHARM
THE BLACK OFF A TELEGRAM BOY.
narrator: OKAY,
WE'LL JUST TELL YOU NOW.
SHE'S THE ONE WHO DIES.
- HIS NAME IS ANDY SOMETHING.
I THINK HE'S
ED MCMAHON'S KID.
A SONG AND DANCE MAN.
narrator:
LUCILLE, MEANWHILE,
WAS THERE
SOLICITING FOR THE FUND-RAISER,
BUT STILL HADN'T NOTICED HIM.
- [snapping]
WE'LL HAVE THE LOBSTER TAIL.
narrator:
UNTIL THIS HAPPENED.
- AND MAYBE LATER YOU CAN...
SAVE A LITTLE
PIECE OF TAIL FOR ME.
COME ON!
- [screams]
- I HOPE THAT ISN'T THE SORT
OF HUMOR
ANDY MCMAHON
WILL BE DOING.
- LOBSTER, MOM?
narrator: AND MICHAEL
WENT TO CONFRONT DONNIE.
- HEY!
NICE HAIRCUT AND THANKS
FOR TURNING MY SON AGAINST ME.
- OH, OH. NO, NO.
I-I'M ANDY.
- OH. SORRY.
OH, HEY.
HOW WOULD YOU FEEL ABOUT COMING
TO A FUND-RAISER AT OUR HOUSE?
HOW MUCH DOES IT PAY?
- IT'S JUST A FREE DINNER,
BUT--
- I'LL BE THERE.
- GREAT.
- I'LL BE IN THE CAFETERIA.
- OH, HE'S SUCH A PIG.
- YOU SHOULD KNOW ABOUT
BAD-MOUTHING FAMILY MEMBERS.
I HEARD WHAT YOU HAD
MY SON SAY OUT THERE.
- HE CHOSE WHAT TO SAY.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
INCLUDE HIM IN THIS.
- NO NEED.
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT POISONED
HIM AGAINST ME.
HOW WOULD
YOU LIKE THAT DONE TO YOU?
- ARE YOU THREATENING
TO POISON ME?
- I'M JUST EXPRESSING MYSELF,
MAN.
- WHAT DID I TELL YOU?
- HOW DARE THAT DONNIE RICHTER.
- YEAH, YOU GOTTA TAKE CARE
OF THAT GUY, OR I WILL.
- YEAH, YEAH. LET ME.
- THIS IS NOT YOUR BUSINESS. NO.
I'M JUST GONNA PULL HIM
OUT OF THAT SCHOOL.
- YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT, YOU ARE.
WE CAN'T HAVE THIS HAPPEN.
NOT NOW.
THIS FAMILY HAS GOT
TO STICK TOGETHER.
- I DON'T WANT GOB
COMING TO THIS DINNER.
- GOOD IDEA.
- GUESS WHERE HE'S BEEN
GETTING HIS MONEY.
- IS HE FOLLOWING PEOPLE
TO THEIR CARS AGAIN?
- HE'S A WAITER!
- [gasps]
- HE IS? WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
- NO, IT'S NOT GREAT.
- AM I THE ONLY ONE THAT
THINKS THIS FAMILY
HAS FINALLY STARTING TO BECOME
SYMPATHETIC AND RELATABLE?
THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE WANNA SEE,
YOU KNOW.
LINDSAY'S TAKING CARE
OF THE HOUSE.
- OH, I FORGOT ABOUT THAT.
TELL THE "HOUSEWIFE"
SHE'S NOT COMING EITHER.
- IF YOU DON'T WANT HER,
YOU DON'T WANT ME EITHER.
SHE'S TAKING CARE OF ME.
SHE GLUED MY THUMB BACK ON.
SISTER'S MY NEW MOTHER,
MOTHER.
AND IS IT JUST ME,
OR IS SHE LOOKING HOTTER TOO?
- WHY DON'T YOU MARRY HER?
- MAYBE I WILL!
- WE'RE VEERING AWAY
FROM RELATABILITY AGAIN.
narrator: MEANWHILE,
MAEBY WAS GETTING TIRED
OF BEING WITH HER FATHER.
- NOW WHAT WE DO IS WE PAINT OUR
LIPS JOAN CRAWFORD RED,
POP ON A LITTLE BLUE EYELINER
AND THEN PLANT A LIPSTICK KISS
ON EVERY ONE OF 'EM.
- WHY THE BLUE EYELINER?
- WELL, SHE FELT THAT HER EYES
WERE TOO CLOSE TOGETHER.
HELLO?
UH, YEAH, UH--
IT'S A CASTING DIRECTOR.
YES, HE IS AVAILABLE.
UH, LET ME PUT MY, UH--
OUR, UH, ASSISTANT
ON THE PHONE WITH YOU.
THANK YOU, YES.
I BETTER GET CHANGED.
- THANKS, DEB.
YEAH.
SO, HE'S TORTURE VICTIM
NUMBER FOUR, RIGHT?
NO, THAT'S GREAT.
YEAH, HE'S REALLY
INTO DISCIPLINE.
narrator:
AND GEORGE MICHAEL WAS ABOUT
TO GET SOME DISCIPLINE TOO.
- YOU ARE NO LONGER
GOING TO THAT SCHOOL.
I DON'T WANNA GET INTO
A BIG DISCUSSION ABOUT IT.
IT'S JUST NOT RIGHT FOR YOU.
- IS THIS BECAUSE I CHEATED
OFF MAEBY?
I'VE NEVER DONE
THAT BEFORE, DAD. I SWEAR.
I JUST COULDN'T THINK OF
ANYTHING TO WRITE ABOUT YOU,
SO I ASKED HER
TO WRITE IT ABOUT HER DAD.
- YOU CHEATED?
- YEAH, IT WAS
STUPID OF ME.
NOW DONNIE'S MET YOU.
I MEAN HE'S NEVER GONNA BELIEVE
THAT YOU WERE UP
FOR A PART IN WICKED.
- YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO.
I MEAN, DO YOU THINK I WANT TO
GIVE THAT SPEECH ABOUT DAD
AT THE FUND-RAISER?
SOMETIMES YOU SAY YOU HATE
YOUR DAD TO GET A GOOD GRADE
OR YOU LIKE HIM
TO MAKE SOME MONEY.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE DOING
A GREAT JOB OVER THERE.
WE'RE KEEPING YOU IN.
- NO--
- I SAID I DON'T WANNA HAVE
A WHOLE DISCUSSION ABOUT IT.
DONNIE. WELL, I GUESS
I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY.
- NO.
- IT'S ANDY AGAIN,
ISN'T IT?
- ROCKY.
ANDY'S THE PIG.
- WELL, YOU'RE NOT EXACTLY--
- I'M HIS STUNT DOUBLE.
YOU THINK I LIKE THIS?
I DISGUST MYSELF.
- LET GO OF MY DAD.
YOU'RE GONNA HURT HIM.
- OH, NO. I'M ONLY MAKING IT
LOOK LIKE THAT.
HE'S TOTALLY
IN CHARGE OF THE SITUATION.
- SO WHAT IS THE PROBLEM?
- SOMEBODY SENT MY
BROTHER DONNIE
A BASKET OF POISON MUFFINS.
- OH, NO.
IT COULD'VE BEEN THE MUFFIN MAN.
THEY NEVER CAUGHT HIM.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
- I SAW IT ON "WHY WE
WERE SCARED OF THE '70s."
- AND WHAT EVER HAPPENED TO THE
MUFFIN MAN?
REMEMBER HIM?
I ALWAYS PICTURED
A GIANT SIX-FOOT MUFFIN...
TRYING TO EAT ME
WHILE I WAS EATIN' HIM.
IT'S KIND OF A FANTASY
I GO TO A LOT NOW.
- AND HE SAYS YOU THREATENED
TO POISON HIM.
- I WAS UPSET.
I'D JUST HEARD THAT MY SON
THOUGHT I WAS A HORRIBLE FATHER.
BUT, NO, I DIDN'T POISON HIM.
- WELL, IF I FIND OUT YOU DID--
OH, UH, ANDY WANTS TO KNOW,
AT THIS DINNER,
YOU WANT HIM TO SING
OR ANYTHING?
- A SONG WOULD BE FANTASTIC.
- SO DAD, YOU SAW THAT?
I THOUGHT YOU DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT I SAID ABOUT YOU.
- WELL, THAT WASN'T
EXACTLY THE TRUTH.
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I KNOW YOU DON'T HAVE ANYTHING
BAD TO SAY ABOUT ME.
- NO. YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK DONNIE WAS RIGHT.
I JUST WASN'T
DIGGING DEEP ENOUGH.
YOU KNOW I THINK I MIGHT'VE
MEANT WHAT I SAID.
YOU NEVER LISTEN TO ME.
YOU DIDN'T ASK ME IF I WANTED
TO GO TO THIS SCHOOL.
YOU DIDN'T
ASK ME ABOUT WHAT I SAID.
YOU THREATENED MY TEACHER.
YOU DON'T RESPECT ME.
HOW CAN I RESPECT YOU, MAN?
narrator:
IT WAS A COMPLEX SITUATION...
WITHOUT AN EASY SOLUTION.
[phone rings]
- HELLO?
- THE CATERERS DIDN'T SHOW UP.
I USED THE CLUB.
THEY SAID WE OWE THEM
TOO MUCH MONEY.
I GUESS ALL THOSE LUNCHES.
I'VE GOT 50 PEOPLE COMING
IN THREE HOURS
AND NOTHING TO FEED THEM,
NO ONE TO SERVE IT.
WE HAVE TO MAKE A GOOD
IMPRESSION, OR WE'RE FINISHED.
narrator:
NOW THAT'S A CLEAR-CUT SITUATION
WITH THE PROMISE OF COMEDY.
TELL YOUR FRIENDS.
narrator:
THE "SAVE OUR BLUTHS" PARTY
WAS STARTING TO HEAT UP.
BUT THE SAME COULD NOT BE SAID
FOR LINDSAY'S CHICKEN.
- WHAT IS GOING ON?
THEY'RE GETTING RESTLESS.
I CAN'T OFFER TO-- [bleep] THEM
IN FRONT OF THEIR HUSBANDS.
- THIS IS WHAT YOU'RE MAKING?
POACHED SALMONELLA?
- IT'LL BE FINE. I'LL JUST
PUT THE SAUCE ON THEM.
- WHAT KIND OF SAUCE
IS THAT?
- WAIT. THIS IS THE WATER
I THAWED THE CHICKEN IN.
- OH. WELL, THAT SHOULD GO
WITH CHICKEN.
- YEAH. [laughs]
- FANTASTIC.
narrator: AND SOME POWERFUL
PLAYERS SHOWED UP.
- GEORGE, BILL KINCADE
FROM FOSTCO INDUSTRIES.
narrator: SORT OF.
- HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
I SENT ONE OF THOSE
STUPID SURROGATES.
- YOU GOT BUSTED TOO?
- NO, I HAD A PRIOR
ENGAGEMENT.
I'M AT THE FIRE AND ICE BALL.
- COMING THROUGH.
CHICKEN IN CHICKEN SAUCE.
- THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR SHOWING UP.
MAYBE YOU COULD SING WHILE
THEY'RE BRINGING OUT DINNERS.
- UH, I'M NOT ANDY.
I'M EMMETT.
ANDY SENT ME OVER
TO LET YOU KNOW HE'S NOT
GONNA MAKE IT TONIGHT.
narrator:
MICHAEL WAS SUSPICIOUS.
I MEAN, THINK ABOUT IT.
WE CAN'T SHOW EMMETT
WITHOUT BLURRING HIM.
- YEAH, HE'S SINGING AT THE FIRE
AND ICE BALL TONIGHT.
- ANDY RICHTER IS SINGING
AT THE FIRE AND ICE BALL?
YOU KNOW, I SHOULD
SEND ANDY A LITTLE BASKET
OF POISON MUFFINS TOO.
- MUFFINS?
- [sighs]
- OH, MY GOD. DAD?
YOU'RE THE MUFFIN MAN?
YOU POISONED 25 TEACHERS
DURING THE '70s?
- JUST THE FIRST TWO.
THE OTHERS WERE COPYCATS.
- YOU POISONED DONNIE,
DIDN'T YOU?
- WE'RE LOSING THEM.
COME ON. COME ON.
[utensil hits glass]
CAN I HAVE YOUR ATTENTION?
MY SON WOULD LIKE TO SAY...
JUST A COUPLE OF WORDS
ABOUT ME.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL NOTICED HIS OWN SON.
- YOU CAME, HUH?
- YEAH, WELL,
IT WAS WRONG OF ME
TO SAY WHAT I DID
ABOUT HOW I FELT.
- NO, YOU SAID WHAT YOU FELT,
AND MAYBE IT'S ABOUT TIME
I DID THE SAME THING.
- SO WHY DON'T WE JUST LET HIM
EXPRESS HIMSELF?
GO AHEAD, SON.
- UM, I WAS GOING TO SAY
THAT YOU DON'T KNOW WHO
MY FATHER REALLY IS.
AND-AND-AND THAT
WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO US
IS A GREAT INJUSTICE,
THAT WE WERE NEVER REALLY
GIVEN A FAIR CHANCE.
BUT THAT'S NOT THE TRUTH.
WE'VE BEEN GIVEN
PLENTY OF CHANCES.
AND MAYBE, THE BLUTHS
JUST AREN'T WORTH SAVING.
MAYBE WE'RE NOT
THAT LIKABLE.
YOU KNOW?
WE'RE VERY SELF-CENTERED.
AND MY FATHER MAY BE
THE WORST OF US.
ME TOO. YOU KNOW,
I-I SEEM TO--
I THREATEN PEOPLE WHO
I DON'T FEEL SUPPORT ME.
- [murmuring]
HE POISONS THEM. ANYWAY,
HERE'S MY ADVICE TO YOU.
GO AND TAKE YOURSELF
A GOODY BAG
AND GET OUT OF HERE
WHILE YOU CAN.
[chattering]
narrator: THE SPEECH WAS
DISTURBING, THE FOOD INEDIBLE,
AND THE GIFT BAGS
PRETTY FRIGHTENING.
AND WHEN GOB REALIZED
HE WOULDN'T GET TIPPED--
- WAIT. NO. NO.
WHERE'S EVERYONE GOING?
narrator: THE SERVICE GOT
A LITTLE WORSE.
- NO ONE'S LEAVING
UNTIL I GET MY MONEY!
I'LL FOLLOW YOU TO YOUR CARS!
narrator: OH, AND THEN
THAT OLD RACIST WOMAN
CHOKED ON BUSTER'S THUMB.
- MY THUMB! MY THUMB!
- THIS LADY CAN'T BREATHE.
narrator: ALL IN ALL,
IT WAS ONE OF THE BLUTHS'
BETTER DINNER PARTIES.
- HEY, WHAT'D YOU THINK
OF THE SPEECH?
- YOU'D DO GREAT AT OPENINGS.
- YOU KNOW, PAL, YOU DO NOT
HAVE TO GO THERE.
I'VE BEEN VERY WORRIED ABOUT
YOUR BEHAVIOR.
YOU'RE ALWAYS
TURNING OFF BURNERS AND IRONS,
AND IT MAY BE O.C.D.
- O.C.D.? NO. I'M JUST
CLEANING UP AFTER AUNT LINDSAY.
SHE NEVER TURNS THINGS OFF.
- WOW. HMM.
EXPLAINS WHY I SAW
HEDGE TRIMMERS
ZIPPIN' AROUND THE DRIVEWAY.
I DID IT AGAIN, DIDN'T I?
I'M SO SELF-CENTERED.
FROM NOW ON,
I WANT YOU TO JUST TELL ME
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND, OKAY?
AND I PROMISE, YOU KNOW,
I WON'T JUST HEAR
WHAT I WANNA HEAR, OKAY?
- I LOVE MY COUSIN.
- I LOVE YOU, TOO, PAL.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
THE BLUTH FAMILY
GETS SOME GOOD NEWS.
- THEY'RE ALL SENDING IN
DONATIONS.
AND YOU KNOW
WHAT THE KEY WAS?
- WHAT?
- YOUR SPEECH.
IT DIDN'T SOUND DESPERATE.
- WELL, I-I GUESS IT REALLY
DOESN'T PAY TO BE DESPERATE.
- IT SURE DOESN'T.
- AND CUT.
[cheering]
- GOOD JOB, MAN.
- LET'S NOT CELEBRATE YET.
WE'VE STILL GOT
THE WEST COAST FEED, GUYS.