narrator: NOW THE STORY
OF A WEALTHY FAMILY
WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL HAD RECEIVED
A WITNESS LIST
FOR HIS FATHER'S
UPCOMING TRIAL.
- WHO'S ON THE LIST?
ANY BLABBERS?
- THEY'VE GOT ONE GUY
WHO WON'T BE TALKING.
THAT IS, UNLESS
THERE'S A HAND INSIDE OF HIM.
- OH, PLEASE, MICHAEL.
EVEN THEN,
I WOULDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
- THAT'S REASSURING.
BUT I WAS REFERRING
TO GOB'S PUPPET FRANKLIN.
- YES!
I GOT HIM IN THE SYSTEM.
- YOU DID THIS ON PURPOSE?
- OH, YEAH.
HE IS RE-DYED, RESTED,
AND READY TO WORK.
OUGHTA BE A GOOD WAY
TO GET SOME PRESS.
OH, I GOTTA TELL FRANKLIN.
- I THINK HE MEANT
"GET FRANKLIN."
- AM I ON THE LIST?
- WE ALL ARE.
- FRANKLIN, GUESS WHAT.
- BUT I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING.
- HE HASN'T
HEARD ANYTHING FROM ME.
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING.
- WELL, YOU BOTH
CERTAINLY ACT INNOCENT.
narrator:
BUSTER KNEW A GREAT DEAL.
FOR LUCILLE ALMOST NIGHTLY
GOT DRUNK AND TOLD HIM.
- YOUR FATHER SAYS HE WANTS ME
TO GO ALL THE WAY TO FALLUJAH.
I THOUGHT HE MEANT
THE SEX ACT
THAT'S SO POPULAR
WITH YOUR GENERATION.
I KNOW YOU'RE AWAKE.
FAKER!
- MORE SIGNIFICANTLY,
THEY'VE PUT AN N. BLUTH
ON THE WITNESS LIST.
- [as Franklin] I HOPE
THAT DOESN'T STAND FOR
WHAT I THINK IT STANDS FOR.
[as Gob] WHOA!
I DID NOT SAY THAT.
- YOU DID, GOB.
YOUR MOUTH MOVED.
YOUR HAND DIDN'T.
- OH. WELL,
I SHOULD WORK ON THAT.
- IS THERE AN N. BLUTH
IN THE FAMILY
THAT WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT?
THEY SAY
THERE'S BEEN MONEY FOUND
IN AN ACCOUNT
UNDER THAT NAME.
- OF COURSE NOT.
THE PROSECUTION
IS TRYING TO TEST US,
SEE IF WE'RE GONNA
TURN AGAINST EACH OTHER.
THEY MAKE STUFF UP.
SHE DOESN'T EXIST.
- YET YOU REFER TO HER
AS A "SHE."
- HE, SHE,
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
- OH, HEAR! HEAR!
IN THE DARK,
IT ALL LOOKS THE SAME.
THEY'RE PROBABLY JUST TAKING
A SHOT IN THE DARKNESS.
- BUT THE GOOD NEWS IS THAT
JAN EAGLEMAN CALLED,
AND SHE IS WILLING
TO CONSIDER OUR CASE.
- JAN EAGLEMAN?
- SHE'S FROM THE JUSTICE TV.
- NOT ANOTHER MEDIA WHORE.
YOU KNOW, FRANKLY,
I THINK I CAN PUT TOGETHER
A PRETTY GOOD DEFENSE.
- OH, NO. HE THINKS
HE'S A LAWYER AGAIN.
narrator: DEVOTEES WILL REMEMBER
THAT MICHAEL
ONCE PLAYED A LAWYER
IN A SCHOOL PLAY.
- [singing] JUDGE,
WON'T YOU THROW THE BOOK
AT THE PIRATE.
- YOU KNOW, MICHAEL,
JUST BECAUSE YOU PLAYED A ROLE
DOESN'T MAKE IT REAL.
- OF COURSE, BUSTER DID GROW UP
TO BE CAPTAIN HOOK.
- NOT COOL, MOM.
- OH, PLEASE.
YOU'D BE A LOUSY ATTORNEY.
THE FIRST PIECE OF EVIDENCE
AGAINST US,
YOU'D RUN FOR THE HILLS.
NO, JAN IS INTERESTED.
SHE CARRIES A LOT OF WEIGHT,
AND SHE IS NOT
CHARGING US ANYTHING.
- [as Franklin] LIKE TO SEE
A WHORE THAT DOES THAT!
[as Gob] NOT THE
"CARRYING THE WEIGHT" PART.
BUT, ON THE OTHER HAND,
IF IT'S FREE--
- SHE WANTS US TO DO
A MOCK TRIAL,
SORT OF A DRY RUN
JUST TO GET US READY.
- WELL, I GUESS
WE COULD ALL USE
SOME EXPERIENCE
IN THE COURTROOM.
FINE, I'LL GO CHECK HER OUT.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU ALL RIGHT NOW,
NO ONE IS GOING
TO LIE ON THAT STAND.
- AND NO ONE
IS GONNA BETRAY THE FAMILY.
- [humming]
announcer: BUSTER WAS NERVOUS.
THAT'S WHAT ALL THE ROCKING
AND HUMMING WAS ABOUT.
AND MICHAEL MET WITH
JUSTICE TV'S JAN EAGLEMAN
WHO WAS CURRENTLY DOING
A TECH REHEARSAL.
- WE'RE DOING A TECH REHEARSAL
FOR MY NEW SHOW:
JUDGE REINHOLD.
IT'S A REALITY COURTROOM SHOW.
- YOU KNOW THAT THERE'S
AN ACTOR BY THAT NAME, RIGHT?
- THIS IS WHAT THEY PUT ME IN.
WHY DID I LOSE ALL THE WEIGHT
IF THEY'RE GONNA
PUT ME IN A POOL COVER?
- I'M SORRY.
ARE YOU AN ACTUAL JUDGE?
- NO.
THAT'S JUST A COINCIDENCE.
I READ SOMEWHERE JUDGE JUDY
MADE $25 MILLION LAST YEAR.
I'M, LIKE, HEY,
I NEVER EVEN HEARD OF THE GUY.
- SO YOU JUST--
YOU'RE DOIN' THIS
BECAUSE YOUR NAME IS JUDGE?
- HONESTLY, THIS IS
THE FIRST TIME
I PUT THOSE TWO THINGS TOGETHER.
- MAYBE WE SHOULD TAKE "JUDGE"
OUT OF THE TITLE
AND GO WITH MY ORIGINAL TITLE:
MR. REINHOLD'S COURTROOM.
NO, NO, NO.
WE'RE CHANGIN' THE NAME.
- THANKS, MICHAEL.
I'VE GOT 250,000
TALKING MAGAZINE ADS,
AND HE WANTS TO CHANGE THE NAME.
- [Judge] MY NAME IS JUDGE.
- HEAR YOU WANNA DO
A MOCK TRIAL.
- MMM.
- YEAH?
- AND WE CAN DO IT HERE
ON THE SET.
'CAUSE I'M LOOKING FOR
JUDGE REINHOLD
TO HAVE
A LITTLE PRACTICE TOO.
- UH-HUH.
- I'LL BE ACTING
AS THE PROSECUTOR.
THAT WAY, I CAN SEE
HOW YOUR FAMILY HOLDS UP.
FAMILIES THAT DO WELL ARE
THE ONES THAT STICK TOGETHER.
- WELL, THAT'S--THAT'S US.
UM, WE ARE GOING TO NEED
A DEFENSE ATTORNEY, RIGHT,
FOR THE MOCK TRIAL?
AND THAT'S NOT GONNA BE CHEAP.
- YOU KNOW THE CASE.
WHY NOT YOU?
[young Michael singing]
- YES, YEAH,
GIVE ME A CHANCE TO SHOW MY DAD
WHAT I CAN DO.
I'LL-I'LL-I'LL SHOW HIM.
I'LL MAKE A FOOL OUT OF HIM.
[cell phone ringing]
WHILE STICKING TOGETHER.
EXCUSE ME ONE MINUTE.
narrator: AND THAT'S
WHEN MICHAEL FOUND OUT
HIS BROTHER BUSTER
WAS IN A COMA.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
HOW IS HE?
- WE'RE WAITING FOR THE DOCTOR.
I JUST PRAY IT'S ONE OF THOSE
THINGS WHERE HE'S UNCONSCIOUS
THROUGHOUT THE ENTIRE TRIAL,
AND WHEN IT'S OVER HE WAKES UP
AND GETS A BIG TOY.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
ARE YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS, MOM?
DID YOU PUT ONE OF YOUR SONS
INTO A COMA
SO THAT HE CAN'T TESTIFY?
- MICHAEL, HOW DARE YOU!
OF COURSE, IT CROSSED MY MIND,
BUT THIS WAS ALL BUSTER.
HE GOT INTO
YOUR BROTHER'S PILLS.
- NOT THE FORGET-ME-NOWS?
- HE ASKED ME FOR THEM.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
I THOUGHT HE WAS DATING AGAIN.
- HOPE YOU DON'T MIND ME SAYING,
BUT THESE THINGS
CAN GO ON INDEFINITELY.
MY MOTHER'S BEEN IN THAT BED
FOR TWO YEARS.
- OH, HOW AWFUL!
WE DON'T HAVE
A PRIVATE ROOM.
- THEY WON'T LET ME TAKE OUT
HER FEEDING TUBE,
AND I'M LUCKY.
I HAVE THE RESOURCES
TO PAY FOR THESE MEDICAL BILLS.
- YOU HAVE RESOURCES?
- WHAT GOOD IS MY MONEY IF
I CAN'T BRING HER BACK?
- BUT YOU CAN'T.
MONEY SHOULD BE SPENT
ON DATING.
IS THAT
WHAT YOU WERE GONNA SAY?
- LET'S GO AHEAD
AND WAIT OUTSIDE.
- SO, YOU COME HERE OFTEN?
CUTE BUTTON.
- HOW IS HE?
- WE'RE STILL WAITIN'
TO FIND OUT.
- I GOT HERE
AS SOON AS I COULD.
OH, THE RED TAPE.
- LOOKS A LITTLE BIT MORE
LIKE RED PRAWN, DAD.
- IT'S THE SHRIMP FEST.
OH, THE SHRIMP.
- DO YOU REALIZE BUSTER'S
PROBABLY IN THIS STATE
BECAUSE OF YOU AND MOM?
HE'S OBVIOUSLY AFRAID
OF WHAT HE KNOWS,
AND HE'S JUST TRYING TO FORGET.
DOES HE KNOW WHO N. BLUTH IS?
- RIGHT NOW, HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHO B. BLUTH IS.
- I'M GONNA NEED SOME REAL
ANSWERS OUTTA YOU PRETTY SOON,
BECAUSE I'VE JUST DISCUSSED IT
WITH JAN.
I AM GOING TO BE PRETENDING
TO BE YOUR ATTORNEY
AT THE MOCK TRIAL
BEFORE JUDGE REINHOLD.
- YOU'RE THE LAWYER?
THAT'S THE SAME REPRESENTATION
CAPTAIN HOOK HAD.
[all laughing]
- IT'S SO GOOD TO LAUGH AGAIN.
- OH, IT FEELS GOOD.
- IT DOES.
THEY SAY SEVEN MINUTES
HEALS ALL WOUNDS.
- WAIT, NOT
"THE JUDGE REINHOLD SHOW"
FROM ALL THOSE MAGAZINE ADS?
THEY'RE ALL OVER THE PLACE.
LOOK AT THIS.
- MY NAME IS JUDGE.
- I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW THAT
THIS KIND OF TECHNOLOGY EXISTED.
I COULD USE THIS
IN MY VENTRILOQUISM ACT.
THERE A BAR HERE?
- WELL, BUSTER'S IN WHAT WE CALL
A LIGHT-TO-NO COMA.
IN LAYMAN'S TERMS,
IT MIGHT BE CONSIDERED
A VERY HEAVY NAP.
- COULD THAT MEAN THAT
HE'S FAKING IT?
- OH, HIGHLY LIKELY
THIS IS FAKE.
ALTHOUGH, THERE DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE VERY MUCH BRAIN ACTIVITY.
-NO. THAT'S HIM.
-I THINK IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
THAT WE REMEMBER
HE'S FULLY INSURED.
I SAY WE SEE
HOW THIS PLAYS OUT.
- ABSOLUTELY.
WE'RE GONNA BE HERE EVERY DAY.
I DON'T CARE
IF IT TAKES FROM NOW
TILL THE END OF SHRIMP FEST.
- WELL, IF THIS YOUNG MAN
GETS BORED,
WE NEED A LOT OF VOLUNTEERS
HERE AT THE HOSPITAL.
TURNING OVER THE BEDRIDDEN,
CHANGING BEDPANS.
- OR THERE'S A MALL
ACROSS THE STREET.
- OH, YOU WANT EXCITEMENT?
WELL, WE HAVE
A GROUP OF YOUNG PEOPLE
WHO PUT ON FAKE WEDDINGS
FOR OUR ALZHEIMER'S PATIENTS.
- IT ACTUALLY WOULD PROBABLY
LOOK PRETTY GOOD
ON SOME COLLEGE APPLICATIONS.
- WOULD I HAVE TO TOUCH
THE OLD PEOPLE?
- ONLY THEIR HEARTS.
YOU COULD BE A GROOM.
BRING A LITTLE GIRLFRIEND
UP THERE WITH YOU.
- I DON'T HAVE A GIRLFRIEND.
- SISTER THEN, OR A COUSIN.
OF COURSE,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO KISS.
narrator: GUESS WHO LIKED
THAT IDEA?
- HE SAYS HE DOESN'T
WANT TO DO IT.
I'M ACTUALLY TRYING
TO RESPECT HIS CHOICES LATELY.
- GREAT. I WAS JUST--
WELL, DON'T ANSWER FOR--
I, UM--YEAH, 'CAUSE I KNOW
EXACTLY THE COUSIN.
I MEAN, THE GIRL.
I WOULD WANT TO GIVE,
AND SHE'LL WANNA GIVE TOO.
AND WE'LL DO THAT TOGETHER
FOR THEM, FOR THE SAKE OF--
IT'S A GREAT DAY...
FOR BEING SAD.
narrator: AND LATER, MICHAEL
WAS PREPARING FOR HIS CASE.
- SO I'VE GOT A DATE
WITH THE GUY
WITH THE BRAIN-DEAD MOM.
I MEAN, IT'S JUST
A PICKET FOR THEM
TO PULL THE PLUG
ON OUR LOVED ONES.
- GIVEN UP HOPE ON BUSTER
PRETTY QUICKLY THERE, LINDSAY.
- LISTEN, I KNOW BUSTER.
I KNOW WHAT HE WANTS.
- OH, I LOVE SOUP.
IF THE ONLY THING I COULD DO
WAS LAY IN BED ALL DAY
AND EAT SOUP,
I'D BE HAPPY.
I WOULDN'T EVEN HAVE
TO TASTE IT.
I COULD JUST
TAKE IT THROUGH A TUBE.
THAT WOULD ACTUALLY BE BETTER,
'CAUSE I WOULDN'T EVEN
BURN MY MOUTH.
NEVER LET ME DIE.
- YEAH, HE WANTS OUT.
ANYWAY, YOU AND I BOTH KNOW
HE'S PROBABLY JUST FAKING.
- BUSY?
- ACTUALLY, I'M--
- CHECK THIS OUT.
MY LIPS DON'T MOVE.
YOU'LL CALL ME UP TO THE STAND,
SAY SOMETHING LIKE,
"WHO IS THIS LITTLE FRIEND?"
AND HE'LL SAY:
- [Judge's voice]
MY NAME IS JUDGE.
- WHOSE NAME IS JUDGE?
- MY NAME IS--
- OKAY.
- THAT'S A SILLY NAME.
- THAT'S ENOUGH.
- JUDGE. MY NAME...
- YES, I AM JUDGING YOUR NAME.
IT AM SILLY.
- IS--
- PLEASE STOP.
- NOW YOU'RE CORRECTING
MY GRAMMAR?
- GOB, NOT GONNA PUT FRANKLIN
ON THE STAND.
AND YOUR LIPS ARE MOVING
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
- JUDGE.
- HE'S RIGHT.
HIS NAME IS JUDGE NOW.
- YOU KNOW, I THINK DAD
MIGHT ACTUALLY HAVE A CASE HERE.
I MEAN, I AM CONCERNED
ABOUT THIS N. BLUTH.
BUT IF IT IS INDEED
JUST A PLOY ON THEIR PART,
THEN THE ONLY
BOMBSHELL THAT THEY'VE GOT
IS A BLUEPRINT
OF AN IRAQI MODEL HOME,
THE SAME BLUEPRINT AS OURS
WITH NO RECORD
THAT WE ACTUALLY
GOT PAID FOR IT.
ALTHOUGH, THIS IS STRANGE.
LOOKS LIKE THERE'S A SECRET ROOM
IN THIS ONE OFF THE HALLWAY.
I WONDER IF
WE'VE GOT THAT.
I'M GONNA GO CHECK THAT OUT.
- OKAY, AND WE'RE GONNA
GO BACK TO THE HOSPITAL.
- YEAH, GOOD.
CHECK ON BUSTER.
WE DO NEED TO STICK TOGETHER
AS A FAMILY ON THIS.
- ACTUALLY, GONNA GO SWIPE
SOME MORE TALKING MAGAZINES,
BUT I'LL MAKE SURE
TO POKE THE HEAD IN.
BYE.
[knocking]
narrator: AND MICHAEL FOUND
THAT THERE WAS INDEED
A SECRET ROOM,
WHERE HIS FATHER HAD STORED
THE FAMILY MEMENTOES,
INCLUDING HIS BIRTH CERTIFICATE.
- NICHAEL BLUTH?
AM I N. BLUTH?
IS HE TRYING TO SET ME UP?
IF I'M N. BLUTH,
I'M GOING TO PRISON.
narrator:
NICHAEL WAS WORRIED.
MICHAEL HAD JUST DISCOVERED
A HIDDEN ROOM
IN THE MODEL HOME WHERE ALL
THE FAMILY SECRETS WERE STORED.
- MY DAD'S TRYING TO PIN
ALL OF HIS CRIMES ON N. BLUTH,
AND I MIGHT BE N. BLUTH.
- HUH.
- THAT'S WHAT IT SAYS ACCORDING
TO MY BIRTH CERTIFICATE.
ALL OF OUR FAMILY RECORDS
ARE UP HERE.
- HMM.
- AND FOR SOME REASON,
THIS STACK
OF BODYBUILDING MAGAZINES.
- [chuckles]
WELL, I GUESS YOUR DAD
MUST'VE HAD THESE
FROM WAY BACK WHEN, HUH?
- MY NAME IS--
- THAT SEEMS KIND OF CURRENT.
- OH! WHO AM I TRYING TO KID,
MICHAEL?
I WAS TRYING TO BEEF UP
TO IMPRESS THAT WIFE OF MINE.
BUT NOW SHE'S AFTER
SOME RICH GUY
WHO'S TRYING TO KILL HIS MOM.
- I GOTTA GO TALK TO MY DAD.
YOU COMIN' OUT?
- NO, NO, I HAVE
TO FIGHT FOR MY WIFE.
I'M GONNA KEEP
MY MARRIAGE ALIVE.
narrator: ONE ROOM OVER,
GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS ALSO TRYING
TO CONVINCE SOMEONE
TO PURSUE A FAKE MARRIAGE.
- WE'D HAVE TO KISS.
WOULDN'T THAT BE KIND OF WEIRD
AFTER WHAT WE'VE BEEN THROUGH?
- WELL, THAT WAS
A LONG TIME AGO.
narrator: IT HAD BEEN TWO MONTHS
SINCE THEY'D KISSED.
- WELL, IT DOES SOUND LIKE
A GOOD TWIST ON A WEDDING FILM.
- A-A FILM?
- WITHOUT THE CORNY
"RUNAWAY BRIDE" BIT
IN THE MIDDLE.
- OH, YEAH.
narrator: AND
SO, LIKE MANY PEOPLE
WHO NO LONGER
FELT ANYTHING FOR EACH OTHER,
THEY DECIDED TO GET MARRIED.
- I'M N. BLUTH, AREN'T I?
LEGALLY, THAT'S MY REAL NAME.
YOU'VE BEEN DOING
ALL THE IRAQ BUSINESS UNDER IT
THINKING THAT
IT WOULDN'T BE TRACEABLE.
BUT IT IS,
AND I'M GOING DOWN.
- FOR GOD'S SAKES,
IT'S A TYPO, MICHAEL.
WHAT KIND OF FATHER
DO YOU THINK I AM?
THEY EVEN GOT
YOUR BIRTH DATE WRONG.
- THAT IS MY BIRTHDAY.
- IT'S CLOSE TO CHRISTMAS.
WAS THAT HARD?
IT'S A COINCIDENCE, MICHAEL.
YOU'RE NOT N. BLUTH.
THERE IS NO N. BLUTH.
- I CALLED
JAN EAGLEMAN ABOUT THIS,
AND SHE SAYS
IT SOUNDS PRETTY BAD.
- YOU CALLED HER?
SHE'S WITH THE PROSECUTION.
- JUST FOR THE MOCK TRIAL.
- YEAH, BUT
WHAT IF SHE WASN'T?
YOU KNOW, I AM GLAD
WE'RE HAVING THIS MOCK TRIAL,
BECAUSE IT HAS SHOWN ME
THAT YOU CANNOT BE INVOLVED
IN THE REAL DEFENSE.
- OH, COME ON.
- WHY CAN'T YOU BE
LIKE BUSTER?
HE PUT HIMSELF IN A COMA
TO PROTECT THIS FAMILY,
POOR KID.
I GOTTA GET DOWN THERE NOW.
- SHRIMP FEST IS OVER, POP.
- REALLY?
BETTER GO TO CHILI'S.
narrator:
BACK AT THE HOSPITAL,
LINDSAY HAD JOINED BRIAN
IN PROTEST.
- ALL THEY'RE DOING IN THERE
IS TRYING TO KEEP PEOPLE ALIVE.
- IT'S A LIFE MILL.
- OH, HELLO, LINDSAY.
I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO A FRIEND OF MINE
THAT I MET AT THE GYM.
- HI. I'M FATHER BEN.
- BEN IS A FRANCISCAN WHO CAN
BENCH-PRESS OVER 200 POUNDS.
AND HE TALKED ME
INTO PROTESTING TOO.
SHOW 'EM YOUR SIGN.
NO, THE OTHER SIDE,
'CAUSE THAT--
- TOBIAS, BRIAN AND I
BELIEVE IN THE DIGNITY
OF EVERY HUMAN BEING.
NOW, WHY DON'T WE LEAVE
THE FRUITS WITH THE VEGETABLES
AND GO GET A COFFEE?
- DO SOME PUSHUPS.
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
AND MAEBY
WERE ALSO AT THE HOSPITAL,
PUTTING ON A WEDDING
FOR THE ALZHEIMER'S PATIENTS.
- AND NOW,
THEY ARE TRULY FAMILY.
IT IS PERMANENT,
ETERNAL.
narrator: AND MAEBY
DID THE THING
SHE HAD ALWAYS THOUGHT
WAS SO CORNY--
- I CAN'T DO THIS.
I CAN'T DO THIS.
- BUT WE'RE NOT--
- WHAT AM I DOING?
narrator: AND RAN AWAY.
- WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
- JUST GIVE IT A MINUTE.
NOW IT'S A BAR MITZVAH.
narrator:
AND AS GEORGE MICHAEL ACTED
LIKE A BOY BECOMING A MAN,
MICHAEL RETURNED TO HIS OFFICE
TO FIND A MAN ACTING LIKE A BOY.
- WHAT'S THIS?
- JUST PRACTICING MY TESTIMONY.
FAKE WITNESS BOX.
- AND YOU COULDN'T HAVE JUST
TAKEN MY STUFF OFF
THE DESK FIRST
OR UNPLUGGED MY COMPUTER?
- JUSTICE IS SWIFT, MICHAEL.
PLUS, WE NEED TO BE PREPARED
FOR OUR TESTIMONY.
YOU'RE NOT DOING ANY OF THAT
"MY NAME IS JUDGE" STUFF
ON THE STAND, OKAY?
- NO. THEY'RE ALL OUT OF
MAGAZINES AT THE HOSPITAL.
BESIDES, I'VE GOT A BETTER IDEA.
narrator: WHICH HE GOT
AT THE HOSPITAL.
- PATIENT PRESENTED WITH
GASTRIC BACTERIAL INFECTION
COUPLED WITH PEPTIC ULCERS.
TETRACYCLINE SHOULD NOT BE
ADMINISTERED DUE TO ALLERGIES.
- CHECK THIS OUT.
YOU'LL SAY,
"WHO'S THIS LITTLE FRIEND?"
AND I'LL SAY,
"WELL, HE'S NOT REALLY
FEELING THAT WELL."
AND YOU'LL SAY,
"OH, WHAT'S WRONG WITH
THE LITTLE GUY?"
AND HE'LL SAY--
- PATIENT PRESENTED WITH
GASTRIC BACTERIAL INFECTION.
- WOW. SOUNDS LIKE YOU
COULD USE SOME TRY-CYCLING.
- TETRACYCLINE SHOULD NOT BE
ADMINISTERED DUE TO ALLERGIES.
- YOUR LIPS ARE STILL MOVING,
AND--
YOU STOLE
THE DOCTOR'S TAPE RECORDER?
- JUST THE TAPE.
- I'M GIVING IT BACK TO HIM.
- COME ON, MICHAEL!
I NEED THIS!
- GOB--
- MY CAREER NEEDS THIS.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
DAD WAS RIGHT.
IF YOU REALLY CARED
ABOUT THIS FAMILY,
YOU'D BE
MORE SUPPORTIVE OF ME IN THIS.
- GOB, I'M NOT GONNA TURN
THIS MOCK TRIAL
INTO SOME KIND OF--
- YOU WERE GONNA SAY MOCKERY,
WEREN'T YOU?
- I WAS IN TROUBLE, LIKE,
THREE WORDS INTO THAT.
narrator: SO MICHAEL
WENT BACK TO THE HOSPITAL
WHEN HE HAD A VISIT
FROM THE REAL PROSECUTOR.
- WAYNE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' HERE?
- WE HEARD ABOUT THE TRIAL.
WE WANNA MAKE A DEAL WITH YOU.
- A DEAL?
IT'S A MOCK TRIAL.
- READ THE PATRIOT ACT.
ANYTHING SAID IN A MOCK TRIAL
OR DAYTIME COURTROOM SHOW
CAN BE USED IN ANY REAL
CRIMINAL PROCEEDING
OR PRIME-TIME PROCEDURAL SHOW
SUBJECT TO THE INTERPRETATION
OF THE PRESIDING JUDGE
OR THE EXECUTIVE PRODUCER.
- IN OUR CASE,
JUDGE REINHOLD IS BOTH.
- DID HE GET E.P.?
- SURE DID.
- GOOD FOR HIM. ANYWAY,
YOU PUT YOUR DAD ON THE STAND,
GET HIM TALKING,
AND YOU GET FULL IMMUNITY.
IF YOU DON'T DO IT,
WE'RE GONNA GO AFTER N. BLUTH,
AND WE THINK THAT'S YOU.
- YOU'RE ASKING ME TO CONSPIRE
AGAINST MY OWN CLIENT.
COULDN'T YOU
GO TO JAIL FOR THAT?
- THINK ABOUT IT, MICHAEL.
IT MAY BE TIME TO CUT AND RUN.
- WE DON'T DO THAT
IN MY FAMILY.
narrator: MAEBY HAD JUST
RUN AWAY FROM A FAKE WEDDING
THAT HAD GOTTEN
A LITTLE TOO REAL.
[knocking]
- OH, YOU KNOW ABOUT
THIS ROOM TOO?
- YEAH, IT'S MY DAD'S
EXERCISE ROOM.
narrator: ALTHOUGH,
FOR ALL HER WORLDLINESS,
MAEBY WAS STILL
A CHILD IN MANY WAYS.
- YEAH, I-I COME HERE
TO THINK MYSELF SOMETIMES,
BUT I ALWAYS KNOCK FIRST.
I-I ALWAYS DO THAT.
I ALWAYS DO THAT ANYWAY,
NO MATTER WHAT ROOM.
- SO WHAT HAPPENED BACK THERE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I JUST GOT
A LITTLE WEIRDED OUT.
I MEAN, WE'RE COUSINS.
IT'S WRONG.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
THE TORAH TELLS US
THAT THE LARGER WRONG
IS TO PUT OUR OWN FEELINGS
BEFORE THE COMMITMENTS
WE'VE MADE,
YOU KNOW, TOWARDS THE SICK,
AGED, AND GROSS.
narrator: THAT'S NOT
IN THE TORAH.
- AND, I MEAN, YOU KNOW,
WE WEREN'T THERE
FOR OURSELVES TODAY.
WE WERE THERE
TO BRING HAPPINESS TO OTHERS.
AND I JUST--I JUST FEEL NOW
LIKE WE LEFT
A LOT OF OLD PEOPLE
SAD THERE TODAY.
narrator: AGAIN, NOT TRUE.
[singing and clapping]
- I MEAN, YOU KNOW,
I'M NOT SAYING
IT'S NOT WEIRD
FOR ME TOO.
I'M JUST SAYING
MAYBE WE COULD
TAKE THOSE WEIRD FEELINGS
AND TURN THEM
INTO SOMETHING POSITIVE.
narrator:
HE REALLY WANTED THAT KISS.
- I MEAN, I GUESS IT WOULD BE
A GOOD WAY
TO FREAK OUT OUR PARENTS.
- LET'S FREAK THEM OUT.
- HEY, YOU GUYS KNOW
ABOUT THIS ROOM TOO, HUH?
I'M JUST LOOKIN'
FOR SOME EVIDENCE
FOR MY TRIAL AGAINST POP-POP--
FOR POP-POP.
- I MEAN, SERIOUSLY, DOCTOR,
WHEN ARE WE GOING TO
KNOW SOMETHING?
I'M TRYIN' TO
GET ON WITH MY LIFE.
YEAH, SO IS
WHAT REMAINS OF BUSTER.
- DR. FARMER,
THERE'S A PROBLEM IN 302.
THE PATIENT'S HAVING
A BAD REACTION
TO THE TETRACYCLINE.
- TETRACYCLINE? DIDN'T I SAY
NOT TO GIVE HIM THAT?
DIDN'T YOU LISTEN TO MY NOTES?
- [Gob singing]
IT AIN'T EASY BEIN' WHITE.
IT AIN'T EASY.
- I'M TRYING TO GET ON WITH
MY LIFE, AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU CAN'T DEAL WITH IT.
- NO, I CAN'T, LINDSAY.
- YOU'RE NOT INTERESTED IN ME.
- AND YOU'RE NOT CAPABLE
OF INTIMACY.
- WELL, JUST FAKE IT!
COMA.
narrator: AND,
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
THAT ACTUALLY
GOT THROUGH TO THEM.
- NOW, WILL YOU PLEASE
TURN ON THE CARTOON NETWORK
AND GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE?
narrator: AND THE NEXT DAY,
THE MOCK TRIAL BEGAN,
AS DID THE MOCK EPISODE
OF WHAT HAD
NOW BEEN RENAMED
"MOCK TRIAL WITH J. REINHOLD."
- TAKE ONE.
IN FIVE, FOUR, THREE--
- [singing] MOCK TRIAL
WITH J. REINHOLD
MOCK TRIAL
MOCK TRIAL!
- ALL RISE FOR
ACTING'S HIGHEST HONOR,
JUDGE REINHOLD!
JUDGE REINHOLD
IS NEITHER A REAL JUDGE,
NOR HAS HE RECEIVED
ACTING'S HIGHEST HONOR.
- WOW. THANK YOU.
THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I EVER GOT A STANDING OVATION
BEFORE THE SHOW.
THEY'RE NOT CLAPPING.
- THEY DON'T IN A COURTROOM.
- PLEASE BE SEATED.
narrator:
THE PROCEEDINGS GOT UNDER WAY,
AND THE BLUTHS
SET ABOUT PRETENDING
THEY WERE A FAMILY
THAT STAYS TOGETHER.
- YOU NEVER HEARD ANYONE
IN YOUR FAMILY DISCUSS PLANS
TO EITHER TRAVEL TO IRAQ
OR DO BUSINESS THERE?
- WELL, I SPEND SO MUCH TIME
MAKING SWEET LOVE ON MY WIFE
THAT IT'S HARD TO HEAR ANYTHING
OVER THE CLATTER
OF HER BREASTS AND--
- YOUR WITNESS.
- I HAVE NOTHING.
[bass guitar sliding]
- OH, HOW SHOULD I KNOW
WHERE THE MONEY COMES FROM?
I JUST KNOW WHERE IT GOES,
TO TAKING CARE OF
MY POOR COMATOSE SON.
AND IF THIS WERE THE REAL TRIAL,
I'D CRY HERE.
- I'M SAVING
MY GOOD STUFF TOO.
- I HAVE NO CROSS AT THIS TIME.
- THIS IS WHY YOU'RE NOT
HANDLING MY REAL DEFENSE.
- I HAVE ONE WITNESS, DAD,
AND HE'LL CLEAR EVERYTHING UP.
- narrator:
GOB HAD A LITTLE TROUBLE.
- STATE YOUR NAME.
- [Judge's voice]
MY NAME IS JUDGE.
- WHAT KIND OF NAME IS THAT,
MAGAZINE?
- I'M JUST GONNA GO AHEAD
AND JUMP IN RIGHT HERE.
I HAVE NOTHING FOR HIM.
[bass string sliding]
narrator: BUT NOW,
IT WAS MICHAEL'S TURN.
- WELL, LISTEN,
HAVE FUN OUT THERE,
BECAUSE THIS IS THE LAST TIME
YOU'RE GONNA SEE
THIS SIDE OF A COURTROOM
TILL YOUR SECOND WIFE
DIVORCES YOUR FRECKLED ASS.
- LOOK AT THAT.
YOU JUST BLEW
YOUR WEDDING SPEECH.
I'D LIKE TO JUMP RIGHT AHEAD
TO CALLING A SURPRISE WITNESS.
- ONLY WITNESSES ON THE LIST.
- OH, HE'S ON THE LIST.
- I WOULD LIKE TO CALL
TO THE STAND
FRANKLIN DELANO BLUTH.
- YOU'RE CALLIN' FRANKLIN,
MIKEY?
- I SURE AM, PAL.
I SUPPORT MY BROTHER.
- [singing]
IT AIN'T EASY BEIN' WHITE
IT AIN'T EASY BEIN' BROWN.
YOU'RE MY BRO,
YOU'RE MY BROTHER
- YOUR HONOR,
THIS IS HIGHLY UNUSUAL.
- WELL, I'M VERY CURIOUS
TO SEE WHERE THIS IS GOING.
I'M GONNA ALLOW IT.
BUT I'M WARNING YOU,
MR. BLUTH,
THIS BETTER MAKE
FOR A GOOD PROMO.
- I WAS APPROACHED BY
THE REAL PROSECUTION RECENTLY
AND WAS ASKED IF I WOULD
BE WILLING TO TURN ON MY FAMILY
AND SAVE MYSELF.
WOULD YOU PLEASE
PRESS THE PLAY BUTTON
ON THE TAPE RECORDER
INSIDE THE PUPPET?
- IF YOU DON'T DO IT,
WE'RE GONNA GO AFTER N. BLUTH,
AND WE THINK THAT'S YOU.
- YOU'RE ASKING ME TO CONSPIRE
AGAINST MY OWN CLIENT.
- WHY DO THERE HAVE
TO BE PUPPETS LIKE FRANK?
- THINK ABOUT IT, MICHAEL.
- WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
WE'VE GOT A MISTRIAL.
BUT ON THE PLUS SIDE,
WE'VE ALSO GOT A HUNG JURY.
HIT IT!
- MOCK TRIAL
WITH J. REINHOLD
MOCK TRIAL
- YOU DID GOOD OUT THERE,
MICHAEL.
BUT IT'S JUST A MOCK TRIAL.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
TAKE IT TO THE GRAND JURY?
- WANTED TO PROVE TO YOU
THAT I COULD DO IT.
I'M GOING TO A GRAND JURY
WITH THAT NOW.
narrator: ACTUALLY,
MICHAEL HAD NO IDEA
THAT'S WHAT HE WAS
SUPPOSED TO DO.
- NICE JOB.
YOU HAVE A REAL SHOT.
YOU ALL STUCK TOGETHER,
AND THAT'S WHAT WINS CASES.
- WE DON'T ABANDON EACH OTHER.
- NO ONE'S CLOSER
THAN THE BLUTH FAMILY.
narrator: THEY WERE.
- I NOW PRONOUNCE YOU
HUSBAND AND WIFE.
narrator: FOR AS IT TURNS OUT,
THE FAKE PRIEST WAS CALLED
TO A PATIENT'S ROOM,
AND FATHER BEN FILLED IN,
NOT KNOWING IT WAS FAKE.
AND THAT'S HOW
THE KIDS GOT MARRIED.
ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
- "MOCK TRIAL WITH J. REINHOLD"
LEADS TO IMITATORS.
- ALL RISE.
BUD CORT IS NOW IN SESSION.
- PLEASE BE SEATED.
- HARD TO SIT WHEN YOU GOT
SOMEONE'S HAND UP YOUR ASS.
- ALL RIGHT,
LET'S LOSE THE PUPPET.
narrator: AND MICHAEL DISCOVERS
THAT HE WASN'T N. BLUTH
AFTER ALL.
- I HAVE AN OLDER SISTER?
narrator: SO MUCH FOR
NOT ABANDONING FAMILY.