narrator:
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
MICHAEL BLUTH BELIEVED HE'D JUST
MADE A SHOCKING DISCOVERY.
- I MEAN, THAT MIGHT BE AN OLDER
SISTER THAT WE'VE NEVER MET.
- WOW. LOOK AT THE BEAK
ON THAT BIRD.
narrator: MICHAEL FOUND THE
PICTURE IN A SECRET ROOM
WHILE LOOKING FOR INCRIMINATING
EVIDENCE AGAINST HIS FATHER.
- I HAVE AN OLDER SISTER?
DON'T YOU KIND OF REMEMBER
HAVING AN OLDER SISTER?
- NOT AT ALL.
WHAT, DO YOU?
- A LITTLE BIT.
YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
"NELLIE" DOES SOUND FAMILIAR.
MOM AND DAD CLEARLY WERE TRYING
TO KEEP THIS HIDDEN FROM US.
- BUT THIS COULD BE ANYBODY.
THIS COULD BE
A DEFORMED NEIGHBOR OR--
- A CHILD THAT MOM AND DAD
GAVE UP FOR SOME REASON
AND WHOSE IDENTITY
THEY'RE NOW USING
TO PIN THEIR CRIMES ON.
THE PROSECUTOR SAID THAT THERE
WAS THAT ACCOUNT WITH MONEY
IN IT LABELED "N. BLUTH."
HER NAME IS NELLIE.
- MICHAEL, DO YOU REMEMBER WHEN
YOU THOUGHT
THERE WAS A MYSTERIOUS
MR. "F" OUT TO GET YOU?
- [singing] MR. "F"
- YEAH, BUT THAT WAS RETARD--
MISGUIDED.
THIS IS DIFFERENT.
THIS IS N. BLUTH.
- [singing] DIFFERENT
- WELL, WHY DON'T YOU JUST
GO TO DAD
AND ASK WHO NELLIE IS,
POINT BLANK?
- SO HE CAN JUST
COVER IT UP AND LIE?
I CAN'T STAND TO HEAR
ONE MORE LIE OUT OF THIS FAMILY.
- AH, THERE'S THE WOMAN
I'M SEXUALLY ATTRACTED TO.
- OKAY. BUT THAT'S
THE LAST ONE.
- WELL, I'M OFF TO THE GYM
TO PREPARE FOR OUR TRYST.
- TRYST?
- YES, LINDSAY AND I
ARE PLANNING A NIGHT
OF HETEROSEXUAL INTERCOURSE.
- YOU CAN JUST SAY INTERCOURSE.
- WE TALKED ABOUT IT LAST NIGHT.
narrator: AFTER A DISAPPOINTING
ATTEMPT AT LOVEMAKING.
- AH, THIS ISN'T GOING
TO HAPPEN.
I JUST WANT YOU TO BE SATISFIED.
- OH, T., YOU'RE ALWAYS
THINKING OF OTHERS.
- I TRIED THAT.
IT DIDN'T WORK EITHER.
- WELL, YOU KNOW, MAYBE I WOULD
BE MORE ATTRACTED TO YOU
IF YOU WERE IN BETTER SHAPE.
YOU KNOW, IF YOU WERE JUST
MORE MUSCULAR, MASCULINE.
DOES THAT MAKE ME SHALLOW?
- NO.
I WAS GONNA SAY
THE SAME THING TO YOU.
MAYBE WE SHOULD TAKE A LITTLE
TIME TO WORK ON OURSELVES,
AND THEN WE'LL PLAN A SPECIAL
NIGHT IN SEVEN OR EIGHT DAYS.
- OR A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
- LET'S SAY THREE WEEKS.
- WE'RE GONNA
GO FOR IT IN A MONTH.
- STARTING
AT THE START OF NEXT MONTH.
- AND WE'RE GONNA CALL IT
A 31-DAY MONTH.
- EVEN THOUGH THIS PARTICULAR
MONTH HAS 30 DAYS.
- OH, YOU KNOW, I'VE ALREADY
PREPARED A LIST OF "WON'TS."
- OH, YOU'RE NOT GONNA BELIEVE
THIS. MY LIST OF "CAN'TS."
- MARITAL LOVE
CAN BE SO ROMANTIC.
- WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- WHAT?
- "MARITAL LOVE."
YOU WERE LOOKING RIGHT AT ME,
AND YOU SAID "MARITAL LOVE."
WHY WOULD I--
narrator: GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS INTERESTED
BECAUSE EARLIER THAT DAY,
HE'D DISCOVERED THAT THE RECENT
MOCK WEDDING HE'D ACTED IN
WITH HIS COUSIN MAEBY--
- WE'RE MARRIED?
narrator: WAS, IN FACT, AS REAL
AND BINDING AS THE RICE PUDDING
THE DISORIENTED PATIENTS
HAD THROWN AT THEM.
- I WAS TALKING
TO YOUR AUNT AND UNCLE.
- OF COURSE.
THEY'RE MARRIED TOO--
EACH OTHER.
- OH, PLEASE. PITY THE FOOL
WHO GIVES ME A BUNCH OF
JIBBER-JABBER ABOUT ROMANCE.
MY RELIGIOUS GIRLFRIEND
JUST DUMPED ME
AND FOR A SIMPLE
LITTLE MISUNDERSTANDING.
I MEAN,
IF SOMEONE WAS ALWAYS ASKING YOU
TO EMBRACE THE HOLY TRINITY,
WHAT WOULD YOU THINK THEY MEANT?
narrator: GOB THOUGHT IT MEANT
A THREE-WAY.
- WHAT? I THOUGHT THAT'S WHAT
ALL YOU GUYS LIVED FOR.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU GAME?
- WELL, MAYBE
SHE JUST WASN'T FOR YOU.
- WHICH ONE?
- I REALLY WASN'T
PAYING ATTENTION.
- THE REAL PROBLEM IS
SHE KEEPS SAYING THAT GOD
IS GONNA SHOW ME A SIGN.
THE SOMETHING OF MY WAYS.
"WISDOM"?
- IT'S PROBABLY "WISDOM."
GOB, LISTEN, CAN I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
DO YOU REMEMBER GROWING UP
WITH A SISTER?
- SISTER.
UH, NO, I DON'T.
NOT REALLY RINGIN'
ANY BELLS.
- OTHER THAN LINDSAY,
OF COURSE.
- OH, LINDSAY!
- WELL, YOU MIGHT NOT BE THE
MOST REPUTABLE SOURCE ON THIS.
- narrator: UPSTAIRS
GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS SHARING HIS NEWS
WITH HIS COUSIN.
- YOU MEAN WE'RE MARRIED?
- NO, IT'S JUST A PIECE OF
PAPER. IT DOESN'T MEAN ANYTHING.
- WE SHOULD SHRED IT.
IT'S CREEPING ME OUT.
- YEAH, ME--IT'S--
BUT IF WE JUST PUT IT
OVER THE DRESSER,
LIKE WE THINK IT'S A JOKE,
THEN WE WOULD ALWAYS KNOW--
- IT IS A JOKE.
- UNLESS WE GET IT FRAMED.
narrator: AND MICHAEL WENT TO
INVESTIGATE HIS MYSTERY SISTER.
- MICHAEL! WHAT A SURPRISE.
- REALLY? WERE YOU
EXPECTING SOMEBODY ELSE?
MAYBE, UH, ONE OF
YOUR TWO DAUGHTERS?
- OH, LINDSAY AND TOBIAS
NEVER VISIT.
[giggling]
WE'RE SO BAD!
- I-I ACTUALLY MEANT
LINDSAY AND NELLIE.
- YOU CALL HIM THAT TOO?
OH, IT'S SO NICE TO BE ABLE
TO TALK LIKE THIS.
- WHERE'S DAD?
WHAT'S ALL THIS?
- COMPUTER STUFF
FROM THE OFFICE.
- OH, NO, NO, POP,
YOU'RE NOT DOIN'
ANOTHER ONE OF THOSE BLACK
FRIDAYS, ARE YOU?
YOUR MASS FIRINGS?
narrator: BEFORE FIRING
HIS EMPLOYEES, HOWEVER,
GEORGE SR. HAD BEEN SURE
TO CLEAR THE OFFICE
OF ITS VALUABLES.
- SO WHEN DO WE GET TO SEE
OUR NEW, FANCY OFFICES?
- SOON AS YOU GET
YOUR NEW, FANCY JOBS.
YOU'RE ALL FIRED.
narrator: THE EMPLOYEES
NEVER SAW IT COMING,
EVEN THOUGH THEIR FIRST TASK
WAS OFTEN TO UNLOAD COMPUTERS
FROM A RENTAL TRUCK.
- NO, IT'S NOT A BLACK FRIDAY,
ALTHOUGH I DID ENJOY THOSE.
NO, THE PROSECUTION'S
GONNA WANT TO HAVE ACCESS
TO THE HARD DRIVE,
SO I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING'S NICE AND CLEAN
FOR THEM.
- WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT THING?
- AN ELECTROMAGNET.
THINK OF IT
AS A GIANT DELETE KEY.
- WELL, I HATE TO SPOIL
YOUR FUN, DAD,
BUT I GOT BACKUPS ON ALL OF THAT
STUFF, AND THIS IS ILLEGAL.
- OH! WELL, EXCUSE ME,
JUDGE REINHOLD,
BUT I AM TRYING
TO PROTECT MY FAMILY.
- THAT'S NOT A REAL
GOLD NECKLACE, IS IT?
- WELL, IT WASN'T REALLY
YOUR 50th BIRTHDAY.
- YOU KNOW, DAD, YOU CAN'T HAVE
THIS STUFF IN HERE, ALL RIGHT?
AND WE DON'T NEED
MORE TROUBLE.
IT'S BAD ENOUGH YOU GOT
BUSTER FAKING A COMA
JUST SO
HE DOESN'T HAVE TO TESTIFY.
- I'VE BEEN TRYING TO GET HIM
OUT OF THAT COMA.
IT'S COSTING US A FORTUNE.
HE'S SLEEPING US DRY.
- OKAY, FAKER,
I'M CUTTING THE CORD.
I'LL SEE YA
AT THE SNACK MACHINE.
- WELL, IF HE KNOWS THAT YOU
DON'T WANT HIM IN THE COMA,
THEN WHY'S HE STILL IN IT?
- FOR SOME REASON,
HE WON'T TELL ME.
narrator:
HE'D FALLEN FOR HIS DAY NURSE.
- BUSTER, YOU'RE SO DEAR.
narrator: SHE'D FOUND HIS
COMPLETE LACK OF PERSONALITY
AND MOVEMENT ENCHANTING.
- I WISH YOU COULD
SAY SOMETHING.
COURSE, IF YOU DID,
EVERYTHING WOULD BE RUINED
'CAUSE YOU WOULDN'T BE AS PURE.
- SPEAKING OF LIVING A LIE,
I DON'T SUPPOSE
EITHER OF YOU HAVE REMEMBERED
WHO THIS N. BLUTH IS.
NOT A NICK OR A NELLIE?
- JUST THE ONE
WHO MARRIED LINDSAY.
- [guffaws]
OH, ISN'T IT FUN
TO TALK LIKE THIS?
[giggling]
narrator: SO MICHAEL RETURNED
TO THE OFFICE,
WHERE THE ATMOSPHERE
WAS PARANOID.
- IS IT BLACK FRIDAY?
- NO ONE'S GETTING FIRED.
NO ONE'S GETTING FIRED.
- BUT WE HAVEN'T BEEN PAID,
AND THEY TOOK OUR COMPUTERS.
- I KNOW WHO THIS LOOKS BAD,
BUT IT'S JUST MY FATHER
TRYING TO ERASE ALL THE HARD
DRIVES TO AVOID CONVICTION.
THE COMPANY IS FINE.
THIS IS--THIS IS FUN
THOUGH, ISN'T IT?
THEY BROUGHT OUT
ALL THE OLD MACHINES.
I MEAN,
THEY'VE SEEN BETTER DAYS,
BUT I'M SURE THEY'RE ALL
FUNCTIONAL, RIGHT?
LIKE TOM HERE.
- I'M 30.
- YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
narrator: BUT MICHAEL FOUND THE
EQUIPMENT FRUSTRATING AS WELL.
- "GOB'S PROGRAM"?
IDIOT.
narrator: AND THEN HE NOTICED
SOMETHING ELSE.
- NELLIE.
- MICHAEL, I GOTTA TALK TO--
- OH, WOW.
K-Y PRO, HUH?
HEY, DON'T GET ANY MOISTURE
ON THESE BABES.
[crackling]
- HEY! TOBIAS.
BUDDY, I NEEDED
THAT INFORMATION.
THIS IS THAT SISTER
I'VE BEEN LOOKIN' FOR.
WELL, JUST HIT "PRINT SCREEN."
I'M SURE THAT WHATEVER'S
ON THERE WILL COME UP.
- OH, LOOK AT THAT.
I KIND OF REMEMBER THESE
BEING FASTER, YOU KNOW?
- WELL, WE WERE PROBABLY
ALL SO JACKED UP
ON AMYL AND DISCO MUSIC
WE DIDN'T NOTICE.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT, I'M GLAD
ABOUT THIS PRINTER LAG
BECAUSE I WAS HOPING TO HAVE A
JAW SESSION WITH YOU.
- WELL, WHY DON'T WE JUST SAY
AS LONG AS THAT MEANS A TALK?
- I FIND MYSELF ATTRACTED TO
SOMEONE WHO'S NOT MY WIFE.
- WHAT'S HER NAME?
- MICHAEL.
CAN YOU BELIEVE IT?
- YOU'RE MARRIED TO MY SISTER.
- DON'T YOU THINK I KNOW THAT?
- I-I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN YOU THAT WAY.
- WHAT WAY?
- PICK ONE.
- NO.
DID YOU THINK YOU WERE THE
MICHAEL I WAS TALKING ABOUT? NO.
- WHAT?
- NO, INTERESTING THAT
YOUR MIND WENT THERE THOUGH.
OKAY. UH, NO.
I'M AFRAID THE MICHAEL I'M
TALKING ABOUT IS ALL LADY.
SHE'S THE TRAINER AT MY GYM.
- THIS THE TRAINER YOU
STARTED WITH TODAY?
- INDEED. CAN YOU BELIEVE
SHE'S A BODYBUILDER?
- INDEED.
- WHAT AM I DOING?
WHAT AM I DOING?
- YOU'RE NERVOUS ABOUT BECOMING
INTIMATE WITH LINDSAY AGAIN.
- I GUESS.
- YOU PROBABLY SHOULD NOT
RUSH INTO THINGS.
DON'T CALL THIS GIRL-MICHAEL.
STAY AWAY FROM THE GYM.
JUST LEAVE IT ALONE.
- WISE WORDS, BOY-MICHAEL.
I'LL TELL YOU,
IF I WASN'T SO DRIPPING AND
DISGUSTINGLY SWEATY RIGHT NOW,
I'D HOP OVER THIS DESK
AND GIVE YOU SUCH A HUG.
HEY, COULDA,
SHOULDA, WOULDA.
- HEY, HEY. NO, NO.
OOH, LOOK.
NUMBER'S UP. LOOK AT THAT.
AH, THAT WOULD'VE
BEEN A SEVEN.
narrator: LATER THAT NIGHT,
LUCILLE VISITED BUSTER
IN THE HOSPITAL.
- WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
- MY NAME IS REPRESENTATIVE
JOHN VAN HEUSEN.
AND I AM HERE TO PROTECT THE
DIGNITY OF THIS BOY'S LIFE.
- DIGNITY?
EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
I'M THE ONE WHO HAS TO
LOOFAH HIS STUMP.
- I BELIEVE DEATH IS WRONG
IN ALL OF ITS FORMS,
EXCEPT LETHAL INJECTION.
BUT THAT'S JUST AS A DETERRENT
AGAINST MORE DEATH.
AND THIS YOUNG MAN
IS ENJOYING LIFE.
HEY! HEY! HUH?
HEY, LOOK AT US, HUH?
WE'RE HAVIN'
A BLAST HERE, HUH?
- HOW THE HELL DID YOU EVEN FIND
OUT ABOUT SLEEPING BEAUTY HERE?
- IT WAS AN ANONYMOUS TIP
FROM SOMEONE WHO CARES
ABOUT BUSTER'S LIFE.
- IT'S NOT RINGING
ANY BELLS.
narrator:
IN FACT, IT WAS BUSTER HIMSELF.
- THEY'RE TRYING
TO KILL BABY BUSTER.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT--
FROM THE VIDEOS.
- WELL, NO ONE'S KILLIN'
BABY BUSTER ON MY WATCH.
THAT IS UNLESS, OF COURSE,
IT'S AS A PENALTY
IN A THREE-STRIKES SCENARIO.
- NO ONE'S CALLED HIM BABY
BUSTER SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
narrator:
MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
HAD CALLED ONE NUMBER AFTER
ANOTHER UNTIL HE FOUND FRANK,
A COLLEAGUE OF THE WOMAN
HE KNEW AS NELLIE.
- I'M LOOKING FOR NELLIE.
- YEAH. WELL, SHE'S
WORKIN' A SOFTWARE CONVENTION
AT SOME HOTEL.
I CAN SET UP A MEETING
AT THE BAR, MAN.
- APPRECIATE IT.
narrator:
SO MICHAEL ARRIVED AT THE BAR,
HOPING TO SPOT SOMEONE
WHO COULD BE HIS SISTER.
- SHE GREW INTO THE NOSE.
NELLIE? HEY! HI.
MICHAEL.
FRANK SENT ME.
I THINK I MIGHT BE
INTERESTED IN YOUR SERVICES.
- YOU WON'T BE SORRY.
- YEAH? I WAS HOPING THAT
MAYBE WE COULD JUST TALK
A LITTLE BIT FIRST, HUH?
- YEAH, MOST PEOPLE WANT TO.
narrator: AND THEY DID TALK.
AND MICHAEL FELT A CONNECTION
LIKE HE'D NEVER FELT
WITH ANYONE IN HIS FAMILY.
- I HAD A LOCKER ON THE FIRST
FLOOR FRESHMAN YEAR,
RIGHT NEXT TO THE CAFE
WITH ALL THE JUNIOR LOCKERS,
SO IT WAS CLEARLY A MISTAKE.
BUT I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING,
RIGHT?
- OOH, YOU'RE BAD.
- I HAD THAT SAME LOCKER
ALL THROUGHOUT SOPHOMORE YEAR.
JUNIOR YEAR THEY HAD ME ON THE
THIRD FLOOR WITH ALL THE FROSH.
- THAT IS WILD.
- I HAD THE SAME COMBO
ALL THROUGHOUT
'CAUSE I TRANSFERRED THE LOCK.
LET ME TELL YOU WHY
I TRANSFERRED.
narrator: HEY, LET'S SEE WHAT
SOME OF THE OTHER FOLKS
ARE UP TO.
NOTHING THERE.
OR THERE.
- [singing] OH, MY, OH, MY
narrator:
OH, MY.
LET'S GET BACK TO MICHAEL.
- IT WAS JOE NAMATH'S NUMBER,
BABE RUTH'S NUMBER,
THEN MY BIRTHDAY.
- THAT IS A GREAT STORY.
narrator:
IT WASN'T A GREAT STORY.
NELLIE WAS JUST
A GREAT LISTENER.
MOST PROSTITUTES ARE.
- NELLIE, THE HELL
WITH FORMALITIES.
I THINK YOU AND I SHOULD
DO BUSINESS TOGETHER.
- ME TOO.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST
HIRED A WOMAN
HE'D SECRETLY
BELIEVED TO BE HIS SISTER.
- HOW DID YOU GET INTO
THIS LINE OF WORK?
narrator: BUT, OF COURSE,
HE'D ALSO YET TO FIGURE OUT
SHE WAS A PROSTITUTE.
- WELL, I WAS BURIED IN LOAN
DEBT FROM BUSINESS SCHOOL,
SO I STARTED WHORING MYSELF OUT.
narrator:
NOT THAT THERE WEREN'T CLUES.
- WHAT DO YOU SAY WE GO UP TO
MY ROOM AND SEAL THE DEAL?
- YOU'RE STAYIN' HERE, HUH?
I WAS ACTUALLY HOPING TO GET
INTO YOUR BUSINESS TOMORROW.
IT WOULD GIVE YOU A CHANCE TO
MEET EVERYBODY IN THE OFFICE.
'CAUSE YOU'RE GONNA BE WORKING
FOR THE WHOLE STAFF.
YOU'RE GONNA BE FILLING
THREE OPENINGS.
- OH!
I HEARD THERE WERE
A COUPLE OF GIRLS LIKE ME
CONSULTING OVER AT ENRON.
narrator: AND SO THE NEXT DAY,
MICHAEL INTRODUCED HIS NEW
CONSULTANT TO HIS STAFF,
WHO WEREN'T THAT PLEASED
TO MEET HER.
- YOU HIRED SOMEONE ELSE?
- YES.
- WE HAVEN'T EVEN BEEN PAID YET.
- THAT'S EXACTLY WHY
I HIRED HER--
TO HELP OUT
WITH THE FINANCES.
SHE'S ABSOLUTELY AMAZING
AT THAT STUFF. RIGHT?
YOU DO DO FINANCES
AND STUFF, RIGHT?
- I DO ALL SORTS OF SCENES.
- THERE YOU GO. OKAY, GUYS.
DON'T BE AFRAID TO PUT HER
IN ANY POSITION
THAT YOU WANT, OKAY?
DAVE, YOU GIVE HER ACCESS
TO EVERYTHING, OKAY?
I WANT YOU GUYS TO THINK OF HER
AS NELLIE BLUTH, ALL RIGHT?
IN FACT, WE SHOULD PROBABLY
GET AN I.D.
WITH THAT PRINTED ON IT, OKAY?
[phone rings]
narrator: BUT SHE DID
HAVE A LIST OF "WON'TS."
- WE'RE GONNA HAVE SOME
GROUND RULES FIRST, OKAY?
NO [bleep], [bleep]ING
OR [bleep]ING
AND NO [bleep] UNLESS
YOU'RE WEARING A [bleep]
OR YOU [bleep]
BEFORE YOU [bleep] ME.
AND IF THIS WINDS UP
ON THE WEB,
I WILL [bleep]
YOU IN THE [bleep].
[women gasping]
- OUR COMPUTERS DON'T EVEN
WORK ON THE INTERNET.
- WHO'S FIRST?
narrator: BACK AT THE MODEL
HOME, GEORGE MICHAEL WAS STILL
TRYING TO MAKE HIS
ACCIDENTAL MARRIAGE WORK.
- I THOUGHT MAYBE TONIGHT
WE COULD POP IN AN [bleep]
IN THE OLD DVD PLAYER
AND SIT AND WATCH IT,
MAYBE JUST THE TWO OF US,
HUSBAND AND WIFE?
I'M JUST KIDDING.
I MEAN, THE STATE OF
CALIFORNIA ISN'T, BUT--
YOU KNOW, THAT'S WHAT
MAKES IT FUNNY.
- I'M WORRIED YOU'RE
TAKING THIS TOO SERIOUSLY.
- [chuckles] ARE--
JUST THE OPPOSITE.
[cell phone chiming
"Wedding March"]
- WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
- I BOUGHT YOU
A WEDDING RING...TONE.
[chuckles]
OPPOSITE OF SERIOUS.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
WAS GETTING AN UPDATE
ON HOW HIS NEWEST EMPLOYEE,
NELLIE, WAS WORKING OUT.
- REALLY? AND ALL THE GUYS
LIKE HER, HUH? THAT IS--
THAT IS GREAT.
UH, YOU MEAN
"AWAY" THOUGH, RIGHT?
BECAUSE OTHERWISE
IT SOUNDS A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
BUT, UH, THAT'S, UH--
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
REAL GOOD.
YOU FORGOT TO SAY "AWAY" AGAIN.
BUT, UH, LISTEN, LET ME CALL YOU
BACK IN A BIT, OKAY? BYE.
[sighs]
NELLIE HAS BLOWN THEM ALL AWAY.
- YEAH, WELL,
I THINK IT'S CRAZY.
YOU'VE GIVEN HER ACCESS
TO EVERYTHING--
THE BANKING--
AND FOR WHAT?
I MEAN, YOU'RE BASING THIS WHOLE
THING ON THE FACT THAT
SHE SHARES A NAME WITH SOMEONE
YOU PLAYED WITH AS A BABY.
- LINDSAY, I CAN TELL
THAT IT'S REAL.
IT'S LIKE THAT FEELING THAT
YOU READ ABOUT TWINS HAVING.
- WE'RE TWINS.
YOU DIDN'T GIVE ME ACCESS
TO THE BANKING.
- NO, YOU JUST--YOU'D GO OUT
AND YOU'D JUST WHORE IT UP,
LINDSAY, YOU KNOW?
NOW, SHE'S DIFFERENT.
SHE'S A LITTLE BIT MORE LIKE ME.
IT'S LIKE WE FINISH EACH
OTHER'S--
- SANDWICHES?
- SENTENCES.
WHY WOULD I SAY--
- SANDWICHES?
- THAT TIME I WAS GONNA
SAY SANDWICHES.
- SO I GUESS YOU HAVEN'T TOLD
NELLIE WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
- NO, I HAVE NOT.
I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR THE RIGHT TIME.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE SHE
TRUSTS ME, YOU KNOW,
ESPECIALLY SINCE DAD
IS PROBABLY SETTING HER UP.
BUT I MIGHT WANT TO HURRY
WITH THAT WHOLE OPERATION
BECAUSE SHE'S CHARGING US
A FORTUNE,
AND SHE'S GOT THIS OLD BOSS
THAT'S CLAIMING
HE WANTS A PERCENTAGE.
- YO, MAN, YOU OWE ME MONEY.
I AIN'T NO DUMMY.
AND IT BETTER BE SOON,
OR YOU'RE GONNA FEEL MY HAND
UP YOUR [bleep].
- SO NELLIE WANTS TO
MEET ME TONIGHT FOR DRINKS.
MAYBE I'LL TELL HER THEN.
- THAT'S FUNNY. I'M GOING
OUT TONIGHT FOR DRINKS TOO--
WITH AN EXCITING NEW MAN.
- REALLY TRYING TO MAKE THAT
MARRIAGE WORK, AREN'T YOU?
- WELL, EXCUSE ME,
JUDGE REINHOLD,
BUT I'M FEELING
A LITTLE PRESSURE HERE.
I MEAN, IF YOU HAD TO HAVE SEX
WITH TOBIAS IN FOUR MONTHS,
YOU'D BE SHOPPING
FOR A WAY OUT TOO.
- I STAND CORRECTED
AND DISGUSTED.
- [sighs]
narrator: AND MICHAEL ARRIVED
FOR HIS MEETING WITH NELLIE.
- ARE YOU MICHAEL?
- YES.
- THERE'S A NELLIE AT THE END
OF THE BAR WANTS TO SEE YOU.
- GREAT. THANK YOU.
OH, IT'S TOBIAS.
- MICHAEL.
LOOK, THIS HAS GOT TO STOP.
I MEAN, FLATTERED? YES.
INTERESTED? NOT TONIGHT.
- I-I THINK I-I SEE
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
YOU'RE MEETING
GIRL-MICHAEL AT THE BAR?
- IT WAS HER IDEA.
SHE WANTED TO GET A DRINK,
AND I KNOW IT'S CRAZY.
I MEAN, I'M MARRIED.
AND THE CARBS.
- WELL, TOBIAS, SOMETIMES LIFE
IS ABOUT MAKING DIFFICULT--
- SANDWICHES. I KNOW.
- YOU READ MY MIND.
- OH, GOD. HERE SHE IS.
- NEXT TO THAT GUY?
- UH, WHAT GUY?
- THAT GUY.
- NO, THAT'S HER.
- HIM?
- THAT'S A GIRL.
I-I THINK THE NAME MICHAEL
IS MAKING YOU LOOK FOR A MAN.
- THINK I'M LOOKIN' AT A MAN.
- MICHAEL.
- YES?
- YES.
- NO, I MEANT GIRL-MICHAEL.
- I'M GONNA LEAVE YOU TWO ALONE.
- SO NICE TO MEET YOU,
GIRL-MICHAEL.
[cell phone rings]
- WHAT?
YES? HI, NELLIE.
I WAS THINKING THAT WE
COULD MEET DOWN HERE.
UH, ACTUALLY, I THINK
I'M GONNA COME UP.
- I REALLY NEED TO SEE YOU.
- YEAH, I REALLY WANT
TO SEE YOU TOO.
THERE'S SOMETHING WE NEED
TO TALK ABOUT.
- I'VE ALWAYS BEEN MILDLY
ATTRACTED TO YOU.
- WHAT?
- WELL, LET'S FACE IT.
THERE'S NO DENYING THAT
THERE'S A HEAT BETWEEN US.
- I'D LIKE TO DENY THAT.
- I KNOW YOU FEEL IT TOO--
THIS BURNING DESIRE.
- I-I-I DON'T FEEL ANYTHING.
I-I FEEL A BURNING
MUTUAL RESPECT.
- I'VE GOT AN OUTFIT
THAT'S GONNA TURN THAT RESPECT
INTO SOMETHING FUN.
- RESPECT IS FUN, NELLIE.
YOU'RE GONNA WANT THE RESPECT
WHEN YOU HEAR WHERE I--
WHERE IS THE LIGHT?
- DON'T TOUCH THAT LIGHT!
- WHAT?
- THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU STEAL FROM FRANK'S
STABLE WITHOUT PAYIN'.
YOU WANT TO BE HER PIMP,
YOU GOTTA SETTLE UP WITH ME.
- PIMP? YOU MEAN THAT SHE'S A--
- LADY OF THE EVENING.
WORKING GIRL.
SHE TURNS ILLUSIONS
FOR MONEY.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL RECOGNIZED THE VOICE.
- TRICKS.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
- DON'T YOU DO IT!
AIN'T NOBODY GONNA SEE
WHAT FRANK LOOK LIKE!
- FRANKLIN IS FRANK?
- [singing] MR. "F"
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST
DISCOVERED THAT HIS BROTHER
WAS THE PIMP FOR THE WOMAN
HE THOUGHT WAS HIS SISTER.
- WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?
NELLIE IS NOT A PROSTITUTE.
- OF COURSE SHE IS.
OH, BUT I CAN SEE WHAT
THE MISUNDERSTANDING IS.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW.
MAYBE WE CAN GIVE HIM
A FAMILY DISCOUNT!
- FAMILY DISCOUNT IS RIGHT,
GOB.
THIS IS THE SISTER THAT
I'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT.
- MAYBE I SHOULD'VE BEEN
GETTING A FAMILY RATE.
OH, MY GOD!
- HOW DO YOU KNOW HER?
- MET UP WITH HER
AFTER A SHOW.
- AND YOU DID THINGS WITH HER?
narrator: HE DIDN'T.
- I DID.
narrator: WELL, IF YOU CONSIDER
CRYING LIKE A GIRL
DOING SOMETHING.
- I JUST WANT MY BROTHER
TO RESPECT ME, YOU KNOW.
I MEAN,
I DON'T EVEN HAVE A JOB.
- LOOK, I COULD USE
A MAN'S VOICE ON THE PHONE,
AND I LIKE
YOUR LITTLE PUPPET SHOW.
- AIN'T SO LITTLE WHEN I
TAKE MY PANTS OFF, LADY.
I MEAN, OBVIOUSLY I'D TAKE
SOME OF THE CRY OUT OF THAT.
BUT I AM NOT A PIMP,
MICHAEL.
SHE NEEDED PROTECTION,
SO I MAKE SOME THREATS,
I WEAR THIS HAT,
AND I COLLECT MY 10%.
- YEAH, THAT'S A PIMP,
AND OUR SISTER IS A PROSTITUTE.
- I'M YOUR SISTER?
- I THINK SO.
I FOUND YOU
IN MY DAD'S COMPUTER.
I THOUGHT THAT MAYBE
HE WAS EMBEZZLING MONEY
AND TAKING ADVANTAGE OF YOU.
AND THAT'S WHY I HIRED YOU
TO DO YOUR WORK AT THE OFFICE.
- OH, MY GOD.
- WAIT A MINUTE. WHAT--WHAT KIND
OF WORK DID YOU DO?
NO WONDER
THEY WERE SO HAPPY.
- I'M SO EMBARRASSED!
- NELLIE, HANG ON A SECOND.
YOU KNOW, GOB, THIS MIGHT BE
THAT SIGN FROM GOD
THAT YOU SHOULD CHANGE
YOUR WAYS.
- NO, I THINK THAT'S GONNA
BE SOMETHING BIG.
narrator: DOWNSTAIRS, MEANWHILE,
LINDSAY ARRIVED
AT THE BAR FOR HER DATE.
- MICHAEL.
OH, MY GOD!
MY HUSBAND!
- OH, MY GOD! MY WIFE!
ARE YOU TWO HERE
FOR EACH OTHER?
- IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
- HOW DARE YOU!
- AND WITH ANOTHER MAN!
- AND WITH ANOTHER WOMAN!
- WAIT, WAIT.
YOU DIDN'T PLAN THIS TOGETHER?
I JUST ASSUMED YOU WANTED
A HOLY TRINITY.
- ABSOLUTELY NOT!
WE'RE A HAPPILY MARRIED
COUPLE.
- YES, WHO HAPPEN TO BE VERY
MUCH IN LOVE WITH EACH OTHER.
- WELL, YOU'RE STILL GONNA
HAVE TO PAY FRANK.
narrator: AND MICHAEL
CONFRONTED HIS FATHER.
- I KNOW WHO N. BLUTH IS.
IT IS NELLIE,
AND I FOUND HER.
- THAT'S YOUR SISSY
COUSIN LARRY.
EVEN THEN WE KNEW.
THAT'S WHY WE
CALLED HIM NELLIE.
DO YOU NOT KNOW THAT EXPRESSION,
MICHAEL?
I THOUGHT WE WERE
ON THE SAME PAGE HERE.
- IT'S A NICE TRY, POP,
BUT IN YOUR OLD COMPUTER
I FOUND A NELLIE.
YOU'RE TRYIN' TO TELL ME THAT
THAT IS NOT MY SISTER?
- YES.
IT'S PERFECTLY INNOCENT.
SHE'S MY PROSTITUTE.
I'M A RED-BLOODED MAN.
I HAVE CERTAIN NEEDS THAT
YOUR MOM CAN'T SATISFY.
narrator:
BUT SEX WASN'T ONE OF THEM.
- [crying] I JUST WANT MY
BROTHER TO HAND ME MY MONEY.
BUT HE'S GOT THAT HAIR.
WHY CAN'T I HAVE HAIR AND MONEY,
AND HIM NOTHING?
[crying]
- SHE'S NOT MY SISTER.
I LET HER INTO THE COMPANY.
- YOU DIDN'T GIVE HER ACCESS
TO THE CASH, DID YOU?
- SHE SAID SHE LIKED ME.
- SHE'S A PROSTITUTE.
THAT'S HER JOB. OH, NO.
THE N. BLUTH ACCOUNT.
- WHAT?
THE N. BLUTH ACCOUNT?
THAT IS YOUR ACCOUNT?
- MAYBE. BUT IT'S ONLY
EMBEZZLEMENT
IF YOU SPEND IT
OUTSIDE THE COMPANY.
[beeping]
IT'S GONE.
IT'S EMPTY.
SHE GOT TO IT.
- WELL, THERE GOES THE COMPANY.
- OKAY. NOW, HOLD ON NOW.
LET'S NOT PANIC BECAUSE I-I KNOW
SOMEONE WHO CAN FIND HER.
HIS NAME IS FRANK.
- THAT'S GOB'S PUPPET.
- I'M GOING TO PRISON.
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD FROM OSCAR
LATELY, HAVE YOU?
- NO.
- OKAY.
narrator: AND THE NEXT DAY
MICHAEL RETURNED TO THE OFFICE
TO TELL THE EMPLOYEES THAT BLACK
FRIDAY HAD INDEED ARRIVED.
- HEY, TED.
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
- NELLIE GOT ALL OF US
OUR CHECKS
AND THESE GREAT NEW COMPUTERS.
- EXCUSE ME.
NELLIE, YOU DID THIS?
- I TOOK IT OUT OF
THE N. BLUTH ACCOUNT.
IF YOU SPEND IT
WITHIN THE COMPANY,
IT GIVES
THE PROSECUTORS NOTHING.
ALSO, IT WAS THE ONLY WAY
TO GET MYSELF THE 10 GRAND
THAT YOU OWED ME.
- TEN GRAND?
WHAT--WHAT DID YOU DO
WITH THESE GUYS EXACTLY?
- THEY MOSTLY JUST CRIED.
YOU'VE GOT A REAL
MORALE PROBLEM HERE.
- YOU CRIED?
LISTEN, I THOUGHT
THAT YOU WERE GOING TO--
- STEAL IT?
- YES.
- BUT I MIGHT BE YOUR SISTER,
REMEMBER?
- WELL, THE FACT THAT YOU DIDN'T
STEAL IT
MIGHT ACTUALLY BE PROOF
THAT YOU'RE NOT.
EVEN IF WE'RE NOT RELATED,
I THINK I WOULD LIKE FOR YOU
TO WORK HERE.
YOU'RE VERY,
VERY GOOD AT IT,
AND WHAT YOU DO FOR A JOB
IS NOT REALLY A GREAT WAY
TO MAKE A LIVING, YOU KNOW?
- I MAKE 300 GRAND A YEAR.
- MARRY ME!
IT'S WEIRD
ON SO MANY LEVELS.
narrator: ON THE NEXT
"ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
GOB HAS A RELIGIOUS CONVERSION.
- I'VE SEEN A SIGN,
AND I WANT TO MAKE THIS WORK.
A COMMITTED RELATIONSHIP
THAT ACTUALLY MEANS SOMETHING.
HOW ABOUT YOU? YOU WANT TO DO
JUST THE TWO OF US?
narrator: AND BUSTER'S FAKE COMA
IS PUT TO ITS GREATEST TEST.
- DON'T YOU YOU DIE ON ME.
DON'T YOU DIE ON ME.
narrator: OH, MY.
- [singing] WATCH US, WATCH US
WATCH US, WATCH US
OH, MY, OH, MY
PARDONNEZ-MOI
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE ME CRY
OH, MY, OH, MY
JUST YOU AND ME
AND ONE MORE IS THREE
[chuckles]
YOU AND YOU AND ME
OH, MY, OH, MY
PARDONNEZ-MOI