[narrator]
IT'S ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
MICHAEL WAS
PREPARING HIS SISTER...
FOR HER UPCOMING DEPOSITION
IN THE CASE AGAINST
THEIR FATHER.
- IF THEY SAY,
"DID YOU KNOW OF ANY FINANCIAL
IMPROPRIETIES?" YOU'LL--
- UNBUTTON MY SHIRT A BIT
AND GIVE 'EM THIS LOOK.
- NOT REALLY SURE WHAT
YOU'RE GOIN' FOR.
- I DRANK A LOT LAST NIGHT.
- WHY WERE YOU DRINKING?
- IF I LOOK LIKE A MAN WHO MADE
LOVE TO HIS WIFE LAST NIGHT,
IT'S BECAUSE I ALMOST DID.
- THAT'S WHY.
[narrator]
BUT TOBIAS HAD
A LOW TOLERANCE FOR ALCOHOL.
- [speech slurred]
OH, YOU LOOK VERY HANDS--
- SO YOU JUST
FINISHED OFF THE BOTTLE?
- I HAD TO. IT'S VODKA.
IT GOES BAD ONCE IT'S OPENED.
- I THINK THAT'S ANOTHER
ONE OF MOM'S LITTLE FIBS.
YOU KNOW, LIKE,
"I'LL SACRIFICE ANYTHING
FOR MY CHILDREN."
- SPEAKING OF MOM,
SHE REALLY DOESN'T WANT ME
TO DO THIS DEPOSITION.
- YOU HAVE TO, LINDSAY. SORRY.
YOU'VE BEEN SUBPOENAED.
- I'M AFRAID I MIGHT NOT BE ABLE
TO BE DEPOSED EITHER.
I GOT A CALL OUT OF THE BLUE
FOR A CHANCE TO PLAY
A VERY IMPORTANT PART...
IN... THE PROSECUTION.
- THE PROSECUTION CALLED YOU?
- I ASSUME IT'S
A CBS PROCEDURAL.
THEY DIDN'T SEND SIDES,
SO I THOUGHT I'D TROT OUT
A VAGINA MONOLOGUE OR SOMETHING.
THEY DID ASK FOR OLD PHOTOS
AND DOCUMENTS,
SO I WENT AND GOT THESE
OUT OF THE SECRET ROOM-- OOP.
- "THE PROSECUTION"
IS NOT A TV SHOW.
IT'S CLEARLY SOMEBODY
IN THE D.A.'S OFFICE
TRYING TO GET YOU TO FLIP.
THESE GUYS WILL BEND THE LAW
TO ENFORCE THE LAW.
- TELL ME THAT'S NOT
A CBS FRANCHISE.
- I'M SERIOUS.
WHY ELSE WOULD THEY WANT
ALL THESE DOCUMENTS?
- FOR SET DRESSING,
SILLY.
THOSE HOLLYWOOD SHOWS
ARE SO INCREDIBLY DETAILED.
- YOU'RE GONNA TELL THEM
YOU'RE NOT INTERESTED.
WE ALL HAVE TO BE CAREFUL.
THE PROSECUTION'S GONNA BE
COMING AFTER ALL OF US.
- INCLUDING ME?
- YOU DON'T HAVE ANY SECRETS.
- OH, YEAH.
[laughs]
YEAH. NO, I--
UM, HEY, UH,
SPEAKING OF THAT.
IT'S ACTUALLY
HER BIRTHDAY SOON,
SO I THOUGHT WE COULD ALL
DO SOMETHING FOR HER.
- WHOSE BIRTHDAY?
- MAEBY'S.
I WAS CHANGING THE SUBJECT.
WE-- NO. YEAH, WE WEREN'T
TALKING ABOUT MAEBY.
BUT SHE'S BEEN FEELING
KIND OF LEFT OUT OF
THE FAMILY LATELY,
AND I THOUGHT MAYBE WE COULD
THROW HER A SURPRISE PARTY.
[narrator]
ACTUALLY, HE'D ALREADY
TOLD HER ABOUT IT.
- I JUST POURED MOM INTO BED.
WOULD IT KILL HER
TO LET SOME VODKA GO BAD?
- NO. VODKA DOESN'T--
- IT'S MY BIRTHDAY IN A WEEK,
AND I BET YOU THEY DON'T
EVEN KNOW.
THEY FORGET EVERY YEAR.
I SHOULD JUST MOVE OUT.
- BUT THEY'RE PLANNING
A SURPRISE PARTY FOR YOU.
THEY WOULDN'T FORGET
YOUR 16th BIRTHDAY.
- OH, MY GOSH.
OUR LITTLE GIRL'S TURNING 14.
- SIXTEEN ACTUALLY.
- WELL, I AM OFF TO BUY
THE PERFECT PRESENT.
MAYBE SHE'D LIKE
A SUIT LIKE THIS.
[narrator]
THAT IS HER SUIT.
- THEY PROBABLY DON'T MAKE IT
IN A WOMAN'S STYLE.
[narrator]
THEY ONLY MAKE IT IN A WOMAN'S.
- WELL, I'M OFF, MY LOVE.
- YOU SEE? SOMETIMES,
SHAME CAN BE FUN.
- SHAME?
- SECRETS. YOU--
YOU SAID "SHAME."
HE SAID "SHAME."
- HOW DOES HE KNOW ABOUT HER?
- HMM?
- DIDN'T HE JUST SAY GOB
SHOULD BE ASHAMED OF HIMSELF?
- NO, BUT GIVE IT A WHILE.
SOMEBODY WILL.
WHAT'S ALL THAT FOR?
- IT'S FOR MY
OUT-OF-TOWN ACT.
- OUT OF TOWN, GOB?
THE PROSECUTION IS WATCHING
EVERY MOVE WE MAKE.
- I'M JUST GOING TO IRAQ.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT.
- YES, I AM.
DAD IS UP ON TREASON CHARGES
FOR BUILDING HOMES IN IRAQ.
- IT'S A U.S.O. TOUR.
- YOU'RE NOT GOING.
- I'M DOING MY
CHRISTIAN MAGIC ACT
MY RELIGION GIRLFRIEND
HELPED ME WORK OUT.
I DRESS UP LIKE JESUS,
WALK ON WATER,
WHICH YOU'VE SEEN.
I'M GONNA DO
THE WINE INTO WATER.
- IT'S WATER INTO WINE.
- THEN I'VE JUST EMPTIED OUT
ALL YOUR WINE BOTTLES...
AND FILLED THEM
WITH FAKE STUFF FOR NOTHING.
- GREAT, HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO
HAVE SEX WITH MY HUSBAND NOW?
- GOB, WE GOT THE DEPOSITIONS.
YOU'RE NOT GOIN' TO IRAQ.
- YOU'RE JUST JEALOUS
THAT I AM THE SON...
THAT THE FATHER HAS ASKED TO DO
HIS WORK IN THE HOLY LAND.
- SO DAD IS BEHIND THIS.
- AND HE WON'T BUMP ME UP
TO BUSINESS CLASS.
[narrator]
LATER THAT DAY,
TOBIAS MET WITH THE PROSECUTOR,
WAYNE JARVIS.
- ...A FLOWER IN MY GARDEN,
A MYSTERY IN MY PANTIES.
- THIS IS NOT AN AUDITION
FOR A CBS SHOW.
- I WAS JUST LOOKING
FOR SOME FEEDBACK.
- IT WAS A LITTLE CONTRIVED.
NOW, WE THINK WE CAN
OFFER YOU A GOOD DEAL...
IF YOU PROVIDE EVIDENCE THAT
PUTS GEORGE BLUTH BEHIND BARS.
- I'LL TELL YOU WHAT ELSE
IS CONTRIVED-- THE ODDS
I WOULD TURN ON MY FAMILY...
FOR SOMEBODY WHO IS NOT
ONLY TRYING TO HURT THEM...
BUT WHO WOULDN'T KNOW
GOOD ACTING IF IT MARCHED
THROUGH THAT DOOR...
AND GAVE THEM HEAD SHOTS
AND DECORATIVE SOAPS.
[narrator]
AND AS TOBIAS WAITED
FOR THE ELEVATOR,
HE NOTICED AN INTERESTING FLYER
PROMISING THE PERFECT GIFT...
FOR THE DAUGHTER WHO DIDN'T
FEEL PART OF THE FAMILY.
- HE TOOK THE BAIT.
- HE'S A CLASSIC
SCRAPBOOKER.
- RIGHT DOWN
TO THE WOMAN'S SUIT.
[narrator]
MICHAEL WENT
TO CONFRONT HIS FATHER
ABOUT GOB'S TRIP TO IRAQ.
- EVERYONE KNOWS YOU BUILT
HOMES FOR SADDAM HUSSEIN.
TELL ME WHAT'S GOING ON.
- FOR THE MILLIONTH TIME,
I WAS A PATSY.
I GOTTA FIND A LOOPHOLE
TO GET OUT OF THIS,
BUT BUSTER TOOK COMA
AND YOUR MOTHER TOOK REHAB.
- HEY.
YOU GOIN' TO REHAB AGAIN?
- I'M BRINGING LINDSAY.
I'M WORRIED ABOUT HER.
- DID YOU GET THE CORKSCREW?
- I SEE THERE'S GONNA BE WINE
AT THE REHAB, HUH?
- WINE ONLY TURNS INTO ALCOHOL
IF YOU LET IT SIT.
- HOW DO YOU COME UP
WITH THESE?
I'LL MEET WITH THE PROSECUTOR,
ASK FOR A POSTPONEMENT.
BUT I'M GONNA HAVE
TO GO ON THE RECORD ABOUT
WHY YOU TWO AREN'T THERE.
IF YOU MAKE A LIAR OUT OF ME,
WE'RE GONNA BE IN BIG TROUBLE.
- THIS CONSTANT BICKERING
IS GONNA PUT ME IN A COMA.
- NICE TRY, DAD.
[narrator]
BUSTER WAS FINDING
HIS FAKE COMA HARD TO SUSTAIN.
- IT TAKES A LOT OF COURAGE
TO ENDURE WHAT THEY
PUT YOU THROUGH,
ESPECIALLY SINCE YOUR MOTHER
SAW THAT WEB SITE.
[narrator]
BUSTER WAS NOT ONLY PROVIDING
MEDICAL STUDENTS...
A LIVE BODY TO LEARN ON--
- THAT'S OKAY. TRY AGAIN.
NO. THAT'S A TENDON.
HE'D BE SCREAMING RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S OKAY. TRY AGAIN.
- [low moaning]
[narrator]
HE'D ALSO SERVED
AS A HUMAN CANVAS
FOR ASPIRING BEAUTICIANS.
- THAT'S OKAY.
YOU PUT TOO MUCH
COLLAGEN IN THERE.
NO, NO. TRY IT AGAIN.
[narrator]
AND A MUCH-NEEDED SET OF TEETH
FOR A DENTAL PROGRAM...
[drill buzzing]
DESIGNED TO ENCOURAGE
AT-RISK YOUTH.
- THAT'S OKAY, TURF.
NO. TRY AGAIN.
[Buster gasping]
YOU'VE GOT YOUR FOREARM
ON THIS WINDPIPE, DOG BONE.
[narrator]
IT REALLY WAS AMAZING
FOR THEIR SELF-ESTEEM.
- I DID IT.
[narrator]
EVEN BUSTER WAS MOVED.
BUT HE ENDURED IT ALL
FOR ADELAIDE.
- I LOVE YOU, BUSTER.
WHAT I WOULD GIVE
TO HEAR YOU SAY
YOU LOVE ME TOO--
EVEN IF IT MEANT YOU'D BEEN
FAKING THIS WHOLE TIME.
SPEAK TO ME.
SAY ANYTHING, MY LOVE.
- ANYTHING?
- [exclaims]
- [yelps]
- FAKER!
- I WASN'T FAKING
MY LOVE FOR YOU.
I DIDN'T WANT TO TESTIFY
AT MY DAD'S TRIAL.
- WELL, YOU'RE A COWARD.
- NO!
- ADELAIDE, HOW COULD YOU
LET THIS HAPPEN AGAIN?
I WISH YOU'D COME TO,
OR DON'T YOU CARE ABOUT ME?
- OF COURSE I CARE ABOUT YOU.
- YOU FAKER!
HOW COULD I LET THIS
HAPPEN TO ME AGAIN?
TAKE A SINGLE STEP
TO SHOW ME YOUR LOVE, GARY.
- AW!
FAKER!
[narrator]
SHE WAS WRONG ON THAT ONE.
IT WAS LOVE
THAT MADE GARY TAKE THAT STEP.
- WHO EVER SAID VEGETABLES
WERE GOOD FOR YOUR HEART?
- [crying]
NO, NO.
NO, PLEASE.
[narrator]
OF COURSE, HE HADN'T
USED HIS LEGS IN THREE WEEKS.
[yelps]
AND MICHAEL MET
WITH WAYNE JARVIS.
- I APOLOGIZE FOR THE REST
OF MY FAMILY NOT BEING HERE.
THEY WANTED TO TESTIFY,
BUT THEY ALL HAVE
PERFECTLY LEGAL EXCUSES.
AND I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT NO ONE IS HIDING.
- MICHAEL, YOUR MOTHER
AND YOUR SISTER ARE NOT
IN A REHAB CENTER.
- WHERE ARE THEY REALLY?
- WE DON'T KNOW.
BUT WE DO KNOW
THE TWO PEOPLE WHO
CHECKED INTO SHADY PINES...
UNDER THE NAMES LUCILLE BLUTH
AND LINDSAY FUNKE
ARE NOT YOUR RELATIVES.
ALSO, FOR SOMEONE IN A COMA,
YOUR BROTHER BUSTER HAS MADE
AN IMPRESSIVE 15 PHONE CALLS
TO RADIO STATIONS...
ALTERNATELY REQUESTING
"I WILL SURVIVE" AND--
WHAT WAS THE OTHER ONE?
- [heavy accent]
"SHE'S OUT OF MY LIFE."
- "SHE'S OUT OF MY LIFE."
AS FOR YOUR BROTHER GOB
IN THE U.S.O.--
- DON'T TELL ME
HE'S NOT IN IRAQ?
- NO, HE'S THERE.
IN FACT, MICHAEL,
HE'S ON THE NEWS-- RIGHT NOW.
[speaking Japanese]
- ARE BEES BETTER AT
SNIFFING OUT DRUGS THAN DOGS?
- I'M SURE IT'S COMING RIGHT UP.
THEY'VE BEEN PLAYING IT ALL DAY.
[woman on tv]
AND THEY DELIVER
INSULIN RIGHT TO MY DOOR.
- I'M SURE IT'S RIGHT AFTER
THIS SERIES OF ADS.
IT'S, LIKE, EVERY TIME
YOU TURN ON THE TV, IT'S THERE.
- WHY DON'T WE JUST GO ONLINE?
- COOL YOUR JAPANESE JETS.
- AN INSURGENT IN IRAQ FROM
ORANGE COUNTY, CALIFORNIA?
- IT'S ON.
- WHY HE'S BEING HELD IN JAIL
AND WHY HE WON'T BE COMING HOME
ANYTIME SOON.
- AND IMAGINE THE IMPACT
IF THAT HAD COME ON RIGHT
WHEN WE TURNED ON THE TV.
[narrator]
MICHAEL HAD BEEN CALLED TO SIGN
HIS BROTHER OUT OF THE HOSPITAL.
- YOU CAN STOP PRETENDING
TO BE IN A COMA.
WE HEARD
YOUR REQUESTS ON THE WAY OVER.
- I'M NOT FAKING IT, MICHAEL.
I REALLY AM THIS EXPRESSIONLESS.
MY LOVE THINKS I'M A COWARD...
JUST BECAUSE I WAS USING
PRECIOUS HOSPITAL RESOURCES
TO AVOID MY LEGAL OBLIGATION.
- THAT DOES SAY COWARD.
WE'VE GOT BIGGER PROBLEMS.
GOB IS LOCKED IN A PRISON
IN IRAQ.
- WHAT?
- SO HE'S ACTUALLY
IN AN IRAQI PRISON?
- NO.
IT'S U.S. RUN.
- OH.
- GOD KNOWS WHAT
THEY'RE DOING TO HIM.
MOM AND LINDSAY
ARE PRETENDING TO BE IN REHAB.
I CAN'T GET AHOLD OF DAD,
AND I HAVE TO FLY TO IRAQ
MYSELF TO GET GOB.
- DO YOU HAVE TO GO BY YOURSELF?
- LET ME GO WITH YOU.
I WAS TRAINED BY ARMY.
I SPEAK THE LANGUAGE.
- YOU SPEAK ARABIC?
- [throaty vocalization]
- WHAT'S THAT MEAN?
- I WAS JUST CLEARING
MY THROAT.
BUT I THINK IT ACTUALLY
DOES MEAN "LAUNDRY."
LIKE A CHILD'S LAUNDRY.
WE DON'T REALLY
HAVE A WORD FOR IT.
BUT THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT I NEED
TO PROVE TO MY LOVE...
THAT I AM A HERO,
NOT A COWARD.
I HAVE MY UNIFORM HERE.
MOTHER BROUGHT IT
FOR THE PHOTO SHOOT.
- WOULD YOU BE BACK IN TIME
FOR MAEBY'S SURPRISE PARTY?
- PROBABLY NOT.
WE'LL DO SOMETHING
WHEN I GET BACK.
WHY DON'T YOU DRIVE
THE STAIR CAR HOME.
BUSTER AND I
WILL LEAVE FROM HERE.
- BE CAREFUL.
- HEY. WHO'S TOUGHER THAN US?
[whimpers]
- CLOSE ONE.
[murmurs]
[narrator]
THE DEPOSITIONS
HAD BEEN DELAYED,
BUT THE PROSECUTION WAS ABOUT
TO GET A LORD &amp; TAYLOR
BAG FULL OF EVIDENCE.
- WE SUPPLY THE GLITTER,
THE GLUE, THE CREPE PAPER...
AND THE READY-MADE
TEMPLATE PAGES FOR YOU TO
DECORATE AND FILL OUT WITH--
MY FAVORITE BIRTHDAY,
FOREIGN BANK STATEMENTS,
AND, OF COURSE-- SHH--
FAMILY SECRETS.
[narrator]
THE SCRAPBOOKING STING HAD
HELPED THE D.A.
GATHER EVIDENCE...
AGAINST PEOPLE AS DIVERSE
AS KEN LAY,
OLIVER NORTH,
BUT, IRONICALLY,
NOT MARTHA STEWART.
- SO DIG UP WHATEVER YOU CAN,
AND REMEMBER,
PHOTOCOPIES ARE NOT
ADMISSIBLE AS MEMORIES.
- SIR, I'M GONNA HAVE
TO GO TO OUR OLD FAMILY
STORAGE UNIT IN RESEDA.
- NO PROBLEM.
WE CAN ARRANGE FOR A HELICOPTER
TO TAKE YOU THERE RIGHT NOW.
- WOW!
THIS IS THE BEST
FREE SCRAPBOOKING CLASS
I'VE EVER TAKEN.
[narrator]
MEANWHILE, LINDSAY AND LUCILLE
WERE AT A SPA IN THE DESERT,
AVOIDING BOTH REHAB
AND THEIR DEPOSITIONS.
- FOUR SAUNAS, THREE STEAM
BATHS, OLYMPIC-SIZED POOL,
AND YOU'RE TELLING ME
THERE'S NO ALCOHOL?
WHAT THE HELL ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO DO FOR TWO DAYS?
- I COULD TAKE THE TOP
OFF THIS GRAPE JUICE,
AND MAYBE BY MORNING--
- OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE, LINDSAY!
GROW UP! YOU'RE 40 YEARS OLD.
- THIRTY-FIVE.
WELL, MAYBE THIS
WILL BE NICE. HMM?
WE CAN TALK AND...
CONNECT A LITTLE.
- I MUST HAVE A XANAX.
- I'LL GO SCORE SOME WEED
FROM THE STAFF.
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL AND BUSTER
CHECKED OUT OF THE HOSPITAL.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY WOULDN'T GIVE ME
A WHEELCHAIR RIDE.
- YOU'RE GONNA BE
SITTING ON A PLANE
FOR 18 HOURS TO IRAQ.
- YEAH, I SHOULD DEFINITELY
GET ONE FOR THE AIRPORT.
- YOU'RE GOING TO IRAQ?
- YES. I'M GOING
TO SAVE MY BROTHER.
- SO YOU ARE BRAVE AFTER ALL.
FIGHTING FOR YOUR BROTHER.
OH, BUSTER, YOU'RE SUCH
A-- [bleep]
- THAT MEANS
SHE LIKES YOU.
- IT'S MORE THAN "LIKE."
I'D GIVE ANYTHING
TO HAVE YOU STAY HERE.
- THEN I WILL STAY HERE.
I WAS SCARED TO GO ANYWAY.
- FAKER!
- OH!
- I KNEW YOU WERE NO GOOD.
- THAN I SHALL GO--
TO FORGET YOU.
- OH, BUSTER, DON'T GO.
- I DON'T WANNA GO.
- I'M GONNA SAVE EVERYBODY
A LOT OF TROUBLE AND SAY
THAT WE ARE GOING.
HE IS GOING. COME ON.
- WHEN I MISS YOUR LIPS,
I'LL PUT A FIG IN MY MOUTH
AND THINK OF YOU.
THEY HAVE FIGS OVER THERE,
RIGHT?
- I'LL WAIT FOR YOU.
WHAT'S THIS?
- CAB DRIVER SAID
HE WENT INTO A COMA...
AS SOON AS THEY
PULLED UP TO THE HOSPITAL.
- WHAT A BRAVE MAN.
[narrator]
AND SOON THE BLUTH BOYS...
FOUND THEMSELVES
IN A STRANGE LAND.
[arguing in Arabic language ]
- WHAT DID HE SAY?
WHERE ARE WE?
- HE SAID HE WAS TAKING
SURFACE STREETS TO L.A.X.
THE FREEWAY'S BACKED UP ALL THE
WAY TO KNOTT'S BERRY FARM.
[narrator]
GEORGE MICHAEL, MEANWHILE,
GOT AHOLD
OF MAEBY'S ADDRESS BOOK...
TO INVITE ALL HER FRIENDS
TO HER SWEET 16.
HE DID, HOWEVER, DECIDE
AGAINST SOME GUESTS
HE FOUND THREATENING.
- I DON'T THINK STEVE HOLT
HAS TO COME TO THIS.
[cell phone beeps]
AND YET HE DID INVITE
MICKEY ROURKE.
AND THE GUYS FINALLY DID
GET TO IRAQ,
BUT BUSTER'S ARABIC
WAS A LITTLE RUSTY.
AND INSTEAD OF A CAB,
HE HIRED THEM THE ONLY
RICKSHAW IN BAGHDAD.
- ARE YOU READY FOR
OPERATION HOT BROTHER?
- I'M NOT READY
TO CALL IT THAT.
[narrator]
THEY ARRIVED AT THE PRISON
THE AMERICANS WERE TRAINING
IRAQIS TO RUN.
- NO.
WHAT'D YOU FORGET?
WALK THEM THROUGH THE--
THE WHAT?
- THE METAL DETECTOR.
- THAT'S OKAY. TRY AGAIN.
- MY GOD! YOU CAME!
- OKAY, OKAY.
- OH, I MISSED YOU,
MICHAEL!
- ALL RIGHT.
[chuckles]
- OR SHOULD I SAY "ROBOT"?
- WHAT, 'CAUSE I'M NOT CRYING?
- MAYBE YOU DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
RAM TO UNDERSTAND THIS,
BUT THERE'S SUCH A THING
AS BROTHERLY LOVE.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
I THOUGHT HE WAS IN A COMA.
- I WAS TRYING TO PROVE
TO THIS NURSE THAT I'M BRAVE.
I NEED TO GET A PICTURE
OF ME WITH THE INSURGENT.
I CAN SEND IT ON MY PHONE.
- WHY WERE YOU ARRESTED
BY THE AMERICANS?
- I WAS DOING A LITTLE
OFF-MISSION STREET MAGIC,
TRYING TO MAKE A FEW DINARS.
AND THAT IS WHY JESUS
WAS OFTEN REFERRED TO AS...
"THE KING... OF KINGS."
QUEENS.
THE KING OF QUEENS.
NOW I WOULD LIKE YOU TO BEHOLD
ONE OF THE LATE, GREAT JESUS'S
BIGGEST ILLUSIONS--
[organ crescendo]
THE BURNING BUSH!
[crowd]
BUSH? BURN BUSH?
BURN BUSH!
BURNING BUSH!
[crowd chanting]
BURN BUSH!
[narrator]
THE SECURITY FORCES
ARRIVED TO SUPPRESS...
WHAT APPEARED TO BE
AN ANTI-AMERICAN DEMONSTRATION.
[stun gun buzzing]
[chanting continues]
- THAT'S OKAY. USE YOUR FOOT.
THE THIGH BRUISES.
WHAT DOESN'T? TRY AGAIN.
- SO YOU WEREN'T DOING
ANYTHING FOR DAD?
- HE HAD SAID, IF I HAPPENED
TO BE IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
OF SADR CITY AND MAMOON,
WOULD I MIND TORCHING
A COUPLE MODEL HOMES?
DAD'S JUST TRYING
TO KEEP INFORMATION OUT
OF THE HANDS OF THE IRAQIS.
- I HAVE A FEELING HE WAS TRYING
TO KEEP INFORMATION OUT OF THE
HANDS OF THE FEDERAL MARSHALS.
- I'M GONNA GO COLLECT MY THINGS
AND SAY MY GOOD-BYES.
YOU GUYS CHECK ME
OUTTA HERE.
- GOB, YOU'RE AN ENEMY
COMBATANT.
IT'S NOT GONNA BE THAT EASY.
I'LL TALK TO THEM,
BUT YOU MIGHT WANNA PREPARE
FOR A LONG STAY.
- OH, SHOOT. I FORGOT
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO YUSEF.
- THAT WAS A LOT EASIER
THAN I EXPECTED.
ALMOST TOO EASY.
- WHY AREN'T WE GOING
TO THE AIRPORT?
- I WANNA CHECK OUT THIS HOUSE
DAD ASKED YOU TO BURN DOWN,
SEE WHAT HE'S HIDING.
I THINK THAT'S IT, SIR.
- [throaty vocalization]
- BUSTER, THIS GUY
SPEAKS ENGLISH.
- NO.
I SWALLOWED A MOTH.
- I'M SORRY IT TOOK SO LONG,
BUT THE CHENEY EXPRESSWAY
WAS BACKED UP ALL THE WAY
TO HALLIBURTON DRIVE.
[doorbell rings]
- LET'S SEE WHAT ALL
THE MYSTERY'S ABOUT.
[narrator]
THAT'S WHEN MICHAEL
FOUND SOMEONE...
THE U.S. GOVERNMENT
HAD BEEN ABLE TO DEPOSE.
- HELLO?
- TAKE MY PICTURE!
TAKE MY PICTURE!
[giggling]
[narrator]
MICHAEL WAS IN IRAQ WHEN HE
CAME ACROSS A FAMILIAR FACE.
- [stammering]
ARE YOU, UH--
- I AM SADDAM HUSSEIN...
LOOK-ALIKE.
WHO ARE YOU?
- I'M MICHAEL BLUTH.
THESE ARE MY BROTHERS
BUSTER AND GOB BLUTH.
- BLUTH? IS HE HERE TO FIX
THE AIR CONDITIONING?
- ARE YOU BOTH
SADDAM HUSSEIN LOOK-ALIKES?
- HARDLY.
INVITE THEM IN.
- I AM BEHAVING LIKE
AN UDAY LOOK-ALIKE.
COME ON IN.
COME ON IN, GUYS.
- I'D ALWAYS HEARD THAT THERE
WERE SADDAM HUSSEIN LOOK-ALIKES.
I'M JUST A LITTLE SURPRISED
TO SEE YOU ALL LIVING HERE
IN-- IN ONE HOUSE...
THAT LOOKS SO SIMILAR
TO OURS.
- SCAR ON THAT ONE DUDE'S
FOREHEAD'S GOTTA BE A PROBLEM.
- THAT'S ACHMED.
- NEVER STOP WATCHING THE TRIAL.
WE ARE ALL FOLLOWING IT
PRETTY CLOSELY.
- THEY PUT THIS GUY AWAY,
YOU GUYS ARE OUT OF A JOB, HUH?
- YES, WE WANTED TO KEEP
THE HOUSE FOR JUST
ONE MORE SEASON.
- I HAVE A BABY ON THE WAY.
- I DO A BETTER SADDAM
THAN THIS GUY.
MY SADDAM
WOULD SHOW HIS TEETH.
- YES, TO CHEW THE SCENERY.
[narrator]
SO MICHAEL DECIDED
THE LEAST HE COULD DO...
WAS TAKE A LOOK
AT THE AIR CONDITIONING.
BUT BEFORE HE DID,
HE DECIDED TO SEE...
IF THERE WAS A SECRET ROOM
IN THIS MODEL HOME AS WELL.
AND THAT'S WHEN MICHAEL
DISCOVERED THE BOMBSHELL.
[shutter clicks]
- BUSTER.
[narrator]
BACK AT THE AMERICAN MODEL HOME,
NONE OF THE INVITEES HAD
SHOWN UP FOR MAEBY'S PARTY.
- SURPRISE.
- THAT'S WHAT I FIGURED.
SO, DID YOU SEND
ONE OF THESE TO EVERYONE
IN MY ADDRESS BOOK?
- YEAH. I'M REALLY SORRY
THEY DIDN'T COME.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
- I DO. THEY FOUND OUT I WAS 16.
[narrator]
AND A LOT OF US
JUST DIDN'T WANT TO DRIVE
DOWN TO ORANGE COUNTY.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- THIS COST ME MY JOB,
GEORGE MICHAEL.
I WAS A STUDIO EXECUTIVE.
I MADE MOVIES.
- IS THAT WHY YOU'VE BEEN
SO STRESSED OUT ALL THE TIME?
- HAVE I BEEN?
YOU KNOW WHAT? I'M A KID.
I'M GONNA START ACTING LIKE ONE.
- WHAT, YOU'RE GONNA DRINK?
- DO YOU WANNA JOIN ME?
- I GUESS IF YOU CAN
RUN A STUDIO--
[drink pouring]
[narrator]
BUT THEY DIDN'T
KNOW IT WAS THE FAKE WINE
FROM GOB'S MAGIC SHOW.
- IT'S GOOD.
[narrator]
AND BACK IN IRAQ.
- WHAT IS THIS?
- LOOKS LIKE A MID-RANGE
NUCLEAR WARHEAD.
IT HAS A RANGE CAPACITY
OF 4,000 TO 5,000
NAUTICAL MILES.
- YOU'VE GOT A PRETTY
SOPHISTICATED KNOWLEDGE
OF THIS TECHNOLOGY.
- MY GOD.
IT MAKES ME WANNA
HAVE AN ICE CREAM CONE.
DOESN'T THIS MAKE YOU WANNA
HAVE AN ICE CREAM CONE?
- IT DOES.
- YOU'LL HAVE PLENTY OF TIME
FOR ICE CREAM IN PRISON.
ICE CREAM SANDWICHES.
C.I.A., UNDERCOVER.
- C.I.A. OF COURSE.
THIS EXPLAINS
WHY IT WAS SO EASY
TO GET YOU OUT OF PRISON.
- I KNEW THAT, IF HE GOT OUT,
HE WOULD LEAD US...
RIGHT TO WHATEVER
YOUR DAD WAS HIDIN'.
[narrator]
THEY'D EVEN
CREATED OPPORTUNITIES
FOR THIS TO HAPPEN.
- GET IN THE CELL, STUPID.
- YOU'RE-- YOU'RE--
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO DIDN'T
EVEN SHUT THE DOOR.
COME ON!
YEAH. YOU GUYS CAN RUN
THIS PLACE WITHOUT US.
AS-- AS-- AS SOON AS YOU
STOP DROPPING YOUR KEYS!
COME ON!
[narrator]
THEY'D EVEN STAGED SOMETHING
CALLED AN "HONOR MARATHON"...
THEY THOUGHT HE WAS SURE
TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF.
- COME ON.
- WE'VE BEEN LOOKIN'
FOR W.M.D.'s FOR YEARS.
- W.M.D.'s?
THIS THING IS AS FAKE
AS ACHMED'S MUSTACHE. SEE?
- YEAH, LOOK. IT'S A HOMEFILL.
IT'S THE COMPANY
THAT MAKES THE FAKE STUFF
WE FILL THE MODEL HOMES WITH.
- WHAT THE HELL?
- WHAT IS THAT,
A RECORDING DEVICE?
- THIS IS OUR STUFF.
I GOTTA CALL THIS IN.
- BUSTER? PLEASE?
- BAKER.
[background: muzak]
IT DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE C.I.A. EAST.
I'LL CHECK WITH C.I.A. WEST.
DID WE BUG A HOUSE
IN MAMOON?
- YEAH.
WE GOT SOME GUY
NAMED GEORGE BLUTH...
TO BUILD HOUSES THERE
SO WE COULD WIRE THEM.
- [sighs]
- OH, LOOK. I'M UNCLE BUSTER.
- [laughing]
- I'M SORRY NO ONE
FROM THE FAMILY CAME.
- SOMETIMES I WISH I WASN'T
EVEN PART OF THE FAMILY.
- NO, DON'T--
- YES.
- I'VE NEVER WANTED
TO SAY THIS, BUT...
YOU MIGHT NOT EVEN
BE RELATED TO US.
- NO?
- 'CAUSE GANGY
ONCE SAID TO ME...
YOUR MOM MIGHT NOT HAVE
EVER EVEN BEEN PREGNANT
WITH YOU.
- YOU'RE JUST SAYING THAT
TO MAKE ME FEEL BETTER.
- NO. I'M, UH--
I WOULDN'T.
EVERYONE STILL LOVES YOU.
SOME MORE THAN OTHERS.
[narrator]
AND PERHAPS
IT WAS THE FAKE WINE,
BUT THAT WAS THE NIGHT
GEORGE MICHAEL AND MAEBY
WENT TO SECOND BASE.
- SO MY DAD WAS A PATSY?
[TV: trial continues]
- WE CALL THEM "UNINTENTIONAL
OPERATIONS VICTIMS," BUT YES.
WE RAN THE WHOLE OPERATION
THROUGH A BRITISH
BUILDING COMPANY.
- THEY CONTACTED MY DAD
FOR THE PLANS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
AFTER ALL OF THAT,
HE WASN'T LYING.
- LOOK, WE FEEL TERRIBLE.
BECAUSE THIS IS REALLY
OUR MISTAKE.
BUT I'M AFRAID I'M GONNA HAVE
TO TAKE YOU GUYS OUT.
TAKE US OUT?
- WHAT?
- I COULD REALLY GO
FOR SOME ITALIAN.
- THERE IS AN OLIVE GARDEN
IN MAMOON.
- I THINK HE MEANS
TO SHOOT YOU IN THE HEAD.
BUT PLEASE, AT LEAST LET HIM
LOOK AT THE AIR CONDITIONING.
- IF YOU'RE WORRIED
ABOUT US TALKING,
WE WILL NOT SAY A WORD.
- DON'T BE MAD, BUT I HAVE
BEEN SENDING THE PICTURES
FROM MY CELL PHONE TO MY FRIEND.
- NOT NOW, BUSTER.
- HE DOES NOT KNOW
WHAT HE'S SAYING.
YOU HAVE?
- UH--
- WELL, WHO KNOWS
WHO SHE SENT THEM TO?
- YEAH. YEAH, I GET IT.
- HMM?
LOOKS LIKE
YOU ARE A HERO, BUSTER.
- WE BOTH ARE.
- WELL--
- OKAY. LOOKS LIKE
YOU GOT US.
WHAT CAN THE U.S. GOVERNMENT
DO FOR YOU?
- WE'RE GONNA NEED SOME
BUSINESS CLASS TICKETS HOME--
AND DIRECT FLIGHTS.
NONE OF THIS STOPPING
IN PHOENIX-- [bleep]
- AND MORE IMPORTANTLY,
MAYBE WE CAN DROP...
SOME OF THESE TREASON CHARGES
AGAINST MY FATHER.
- AND I DO BELIEVE
THERE WAS SOME MENTION
OF SOME ICE CREAM.
[narrator]
AND SO, WITH OPERATION
HOT BROTHER A SUCCESS,
OUR AMERICAN HEROES
LEFT IRAQ.
- TAKE CONDOLEEZZA RICE LANE.
IT'S QUICKER.
[narrator]
MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.
ON THE NEXT
ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT.
TOBIAS GIVES HIS DAUGHTER
THE GIFT HE'D STAYED UP
ALL NIGHT MAKING.
- AND HERE'S A PICTURE
OF YOUR MOTHER PREGNANT.
AND HERE'S A WHOLE SERIES
OF YOUR HEAD STARTING
TO CROWN.
LOOK AT YOU-- SO FULL
OF WONDER AND SHOCK.
YOU STILL DO IT.
AND SO DOES HE!
[laughing]
BOY, YOU GUYS
REALLY ARE RELATED.
[narrator]
AND MICHAEL AND GOB
MAKE AN INTERESTING DISCOVERY.
- [translator on TV]
I'M TELLING YOU,
YOU'VE GOT THE WRONG GUY.
THE REAL SADDAM
HAS A SCAR ON HIS HEAD.
I'M NO SCAR. I'M NO SCAR.
- OH, MY GOD.
DOT-COM.
[translator]