narrator:
THIS IS MICHAEL BLUTH.
RIGHT NOW HE'S BEING HONORED
BY HIS FAMILY.
- THREE YEARS AGO
I MADE A CHOICE
TO KEEP THIS FAMILY TOGETHER.
TODAY, IT LOOKS LIKE
I SUCCEEDED.
narrator:
SO WHY IS THIS MAN CRYING?
BECAUSE NOW HE'LL HAVE TO
STAY WITH THESE PEOPLE
FOR A LONG, LONG TIME.
NOW THE STORY OF A WEALTHY
FAMILY WHO LOST EVERYTHING
AND THE ONE SON
WHO HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
DAYS EARLIER, MICHAEL AWOKE
TO FIND HIS SON IN HIS BED.
- HEY, ARE YOU SCARED
OF A MONSTER?
- KIND OF.
narrator: IT WAS THE MONSTER
CALLED LUST,
TO WHICH
HE'D RECENTLY SUCCUMBED.
- AND THERE'S A CHANCE YOU MIGHT
NOT EVEN BE RELATED TO US.
narrator: AND ALTHOUGH HE'D ONLY
GOTTEN TO SECOND BASE,
HE'D GONE IN HEAD FIRST,
LIKE PETE ROSE.
THEN THEY BOTH GOT
SOME DISTRESSING NEWS.
- AND THERE YOU ARE, MAEBY,
COMING OUT OF YOUR MOTHER'S
THIRD BASE.
YOU GUYS REALLY ARE RELATED.
narrator: AND THAT NIGHT--
- YOU'RE NOT SLEEPING
IN HERE NOW.
- YEAH, YOU THINK
THAT'S A BAD IDEA?
- WHAT, I MEAN, SO WE CAN
MAKE OUT EVERY NIGHT?
- DOES THAT NOT WORK
FOR YOUR SCHEDULE?
I MEAN, I'M SURE
WE CAN CONTROL OUR--
I'M GONNA GO SLEEP
WITH MY DAD.
- I'M GONNA GET MY JOB BACK.
- YOU'RE PROBABLY JUST A LITTLE
ANXIOUS BECAUSE YOUR OLD MAN
IS ABOUT TO START RUNNING
A SUCCESSFUL COMPANY
FOR A CHANGE.
- SO POP-POP IS DEFINITELY
INNOCENT, HUH?
- NO, NOT BY A LONG SHOT,
BUT THEY HAVE DROPPED
ALL THE CHARGES
AND NOT JUST THE IRAQ ONES.
THE EMBEZZLEMENT,
THE PENSION ROBBING.
I DON'T KNOW WHY THEY DROPPED
THEM, BUT THEY DID.
LET'S SEE IF WE ARE ON
"MAD MONEY," HUH?
- AND THEY DELIVER INSULIN
RIGHT TO MY DOOR.
- IT'S PROBABLY ON
RIGHT AFTER THIS AD.
THIS IS GONNA BE GREAT FOR US.
IT'S GONNA GIVE US A CHANCE
TO SPEND SOME TIME TOGETHER,
YOU KNOW?
IT'S, LIKE, I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON
IN YOUR LIFE RIGHT NOW.
ARE THERE ANY GIRLS OR--
- ACTUALLY, I'VE BEEN WRESTLING
WITH SOME PRETTY TABOO--
- THE BLUTHS. I LOVE THESE GUYS.
- SHH, HERE IT IS.
- THEY BEAT THE TREASON CHARGES.
WE HAD IT AS A DON'T BUY.
LET'S BUMP IT UP TO A RISKY.
- RISKY! THERE IT IS,
WE'RE DOING IT, HUH?
ARE YOU HAPPY?
- I'M REALLY HAPPY.
I WONDER IF WE SHOULD
MOVE OUT OF TOWN.
- WHAT?
- I FEEL LIKE WE'VE HEARD
THIS WHOLE OUT OF THE WOODS
THING A LOT, YOU KNOW.
AND I JUST WOULDN'T MIND--
- WHAT HAVE I ALWAYS SAID
IS THE MOST IMPORTANT THING?
- FAMILY.
- I WAS GONNA SAY
BREAKFAST, BUT--
WHY DON'T WE GO
OVER TO GANGY'S,
HAVE A LITTLE OF BOTH?
LATER, WE CAN TALK
ALL THIS OUT, HUH?
- I'VE HEARD THAT
A COUPLE TIMES TOO.
narrator:
AND SO THE FAMILY GATHERED
FOR A CELEBRATORY BRUNCH,
CATERED BY A LOCAL RESTAURANT.
- HELLO.
[chanting]
- RISKY! RISKY! RISKY!
crunch!
- LOOK AT THAT, BUSTER.
YOU WOULD HAVE LOST
A HAND ANYWAY.
[tapping glass]
- I'D LIKE TO MAKE
AN ANNOUNCEMENT.
WE NEED TO FINISH THE PARTY
WE STARTED THREE YEARS AGO.
FINALLY NAME MICHAEL C.E.O.
OF A THRIVING COMPANY.
[all cheering]
WE'LL PROVE TO THE WORLD
THAT NOTHING CAN TEAR APART
THE BLUTH FAMILY.
IN FACT, I'VE ALREADY RENTED
THE SAME BOAT.
- OH, I'M NOT COMFORTABLE
NEAR THE OCEAN
SINCE THE SEAL ATTACK.
THE OCEAN IS
MY SECOND BIGGEST FEAR.
- GOOD, DON'T COME.
I NEED TO BE RUBBING ELBOWS,
NOT WORKING YOUR FORK.
- WE'LL FIND A NEW VENUE.
- OH, AND BEFORE I FORGET.
NO MAGIC, GOB.
- WHERE IS GOB?
- OH, WHO KNOWS? I DON'T EVEN
KNOW WHERE HE LIVES.
- HE DOESN'T LIVE AT MICHAEL'S?
- I'VE ALWAYS PICTURED HIM
IN A LIGHTHOUSE.
- DOESN'T MATTER.
MOM, I'M JUST REALLY FLATTERED
THAT YOU'RE WILLING TO DO THIS.
AND I WAS HALF WORRIED THAT
YOU'D ALL BE EAGER
TO SELL YOUR SHARES
AND CASH OUT.
- WE CAN DO THAT?
- YEAH, BUT STAN SITWELL'S
ALWAYS HAD A WILD HAIR
TO BUY THIS BUSINESS.
- IT'S THE ONLY HAIR
HE'S GOT.
WHAT? HE'S AN ALPACA.
- HE HAS ALOPECIA.
LINDSAY, YOU KNOW, IF WE DID
SELL, IT WOULD ONLY MEAN LIKE,
WHAT, TWO MILLION DOLLARS EACH.
[all chanting]
TWO MILLION! TWO MILLION!
- THAT SOUNDS LIKE A LOT MORE
THAN IT ACTUALLY IS.
YOU'VE ALREADY SPENT
$1,200 ON EGGS,
AND THAT
WOULD BE IT FOREVER.
KEEP IN MIND,
WE ARE BUILDING SOMETHING
THAT IS NOT ONLY FOR OUR KIDS,
IT'S ALSO FOR GEORGE MICHAEL
AND MAEBY'S KIDS TOO.
- WE CAN'T HAVE KIDS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER--
WHAT ARE YOU SAY--
IT'S NOT EVEN
AN OPTION REALLY.
- WELL, EVENTUALLY
YOU'LL WANT TO.
- SURE, I MAY WANT TO,
YOU KNOW, NOW.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
EITHER WAY, I WON'T DO
ANYTHING ABOUT IT. COME ON!
- MICHAEL'S RIGHT.
AND I, FOR ONE,
WILL NOT GO BACK TO WONDERING
WHETHER THERE'S GOING TO
BE ENOUGH FOOD ON THE TABLE.
[table creaking]
- MIGHT WANNA START WORRYING
ABOUT THE TABLE.
- IT'S FINE FOR YOU TO SAY,
"DON'T SELL,"
BUT I'M GONNA BE 40
IN THREE YEARS, YOU KNOW?
- YOU KNOW, BEING TWINS,
OUR BIRTHDAYS ARE PRETTY CLOSE
TO ONE ANOTHER.
- YEAH, BUT A 40-YEAR-OLD WOMAN
HAS AS MUCH CHANCE
OF GETTING MARRIED
AS SHE DOES OF GETTING
ATTACKED BY A SHARK.
- [screams]
OH, I'M SORRY, I THOUGHT YOU
WERE GOING TO SAY SEAL.
- OR A SEAL.
- OH, GOD!
- LINDSAY, YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
YOU'RE A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
ANY MAN WOULD BE LUCKY
TO HAVE YOU.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD GIVEN THIS
SPEECH MANY TIMES TO LINDSAY.
- I'M A GIANT FAT PIG.
- I DON'T KNOW WHY
YOU SAY STUFF LIKE THAT.
GIRLS JUST GROW
FASTER THAN BOYS.
- DINNER'S READY.
WE'RE HAVING LINDSAY CHOPS.
WHAT? I WANT HER TO BE PREPARED
IN CASE SOME BULLY AT SCHOOL
IS AS CLEVER AS I AM.
narrator: NO BULLY
EVER WOULD BE.
- OH, LET'S NOT FORGET,
YOU'RE ALREADY MARRIED.
- HEY, MIKEY.
- YES.
- I THINK I'M GONNA
CASH OUT MYSELF,
AND MAYBE GO DOWN
TO MY LITTLE PLACE IN CABO.
- WHAT LITTLE PLACE
IN CABO, DAD?
DID YOU BUILD YOURSELF
A LITTLE HIDEOUT
IN CASE YOU NEEDED TO ESCAPE?
- OF COURSE NOT.
- WELL, I DON'T WANT YOU
TO WORRY, DAD.
THERE'S GONNA BE PLENTY
OF MONEY TO BE MADE
FROM A BUSINESS RUN HONESTLY.
- OH! WELL, YOUR MOM'S
NOT GONNA ALLOW FOR THAT.
SHE'LL DO WHATEVER IT TAKES
TO GET HER WAY.
YOU THINK THE BANANA STAND
WAS OUR IDEA?
- IT WASN'T?
narrator: IT WASN'T.
ALTHOUGH THEY MARKETED
THE IDEA BETTER,
THE FROZEN BANANA ITSELF
WAS THE BRAINCHILD
OF A KOREAN IMMIGRANT
WHO THREATENED TO SUE THEM.
- YOUR MOTHER SAID
SHE'D TAKE CARE OF IT.
THE GUY WAS DEPORTED
TO KOREA THE NEXT DAY.
narrator: WHERE HIS BUSINESS
NEVER RECOVERED.
- YOU TRYING TO TELL ME
THAT ALL YOUR CRIMES,
ALL YOUR DISHONESTY,
SHE WAS BEHIND IT ALL?
- SHE'S THE QUEEN, MICHAEL.
I WAS HER KING,
AND NOW IT'S YOU.
SHE MAY APPEAR ALL SWEET
AND INNOCENT AND LIGHT,
BUT SHE HAS A WAY
OF CONTROLLING YOUR BEHAVIOR.
I'M CONCERNED ABOUT YOU.
BECAUSE I DO NOT WANT TO SEE--
- HE'LL BE FINE.
- YOU'LL BE FINE.
narrator: MICHAEL WENT TO CANCEL
THE RESERVATION
ON THE PARTY BOAT
BUSTER SO FEARED.
- GOB!
narrator: WHEN HE SAW GOB
ON A PARTY BOAT OF HIS OWN.
- YOU MIGHT WANNA UNTIE
THESE ROPES FIRST.
- DON'T TELL ME
HOW TO FLEE, MICHAEL.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I KINDA LIVE HERE.
- LIGHTHOUSE WASN'T FAR OFF.
PERHAPS YOU CAN TELL ME
HOW YOU CAN AFFORD A BOAT.
- YOU MEAN ON THE PALTRY
1,500 A WEEK YOU GIVE ME?
- I GIVE YOU 500 A WEEK.
- YEAH, WELL, SOMEBODY'S DRAWING
A LITTLE ONE ON THOSE CHECKS.
NO BIG DEAL.
I WAS PLANNING ON USING MY BLUTH
COMPANY STOCK TO PAY FOR IT.
SITWELL'S MADE ME
A PRETTY NICE LITTLE OFFER.
- ABOUT THAT, GOB,
YOU CANNOT SELL NOW.
- I HAVE TO.
- GOB, YOU'RE GONNA
BURN THROUGH THIS MONEY
AND HAVE NOTHING, ALL RIGHT?
YOU GIVE A MAN A FISH,
HE'LL EAT FOR A NIGHT.
IF YOU TEACH A MAN
TO FISH--
- HE'LL WANNA USE YOUR YACHT.
AND I DON'T WANT THIS THING
SMELLING LIKE FISH.
I'M BURNING
THROUGH MY FUTURE FOR IT.
BUT YOU WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND THAT
BECAUSE YOU'RE A ROBOT.
ALTHOUGH I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'D BE WILLING TO
HAVE THE COMPANY BUY IT.
- WELL, YOU CAN'T LET GOB
SELL THOSE SHARES.
- WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
HE WON'T GIVE UP THE YACHT.
- OW! OW! OW!
- KEEP YOUR WEIGHT OFF IT.
- SO LEASE IT TO HIM
THROUGH THE COMPANY.
- YEAH, THAT JUST
DOESN'T FEEL RIGHT.
- OH, REALLY?
HOW WOULD IT FEEL
TO LOSE THE COMPANY
TO A MAN WHO HAS LESS HAIR
ON HIS [bleep]
THAN I HAVE ON MY [bleep].
- IT CAN'T BE WORSE
THAN HEARING THAT JUST WAS.
- I COULDN'T SEE THROUGH
THE GLASSES,
AND I SLID
INTO THE LADDER.
- GIVE GOB THE BOAT.
WE NEED TO SHOW THE SHAREHOLDERS
AT THIS PARTY
THAT THE FAMILY IS UNITED.
IT'S A VERY SMALL CONCESSION
TO AN IMPORTANT CAUSE.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL SOLD
OUT JUST A LITTLE.
- FINE, I WILL GIVE HIM
THE YACHT.
- HEY, DAD.
- HEY, PAL.
- WELL, YOU SAID
WE COULD TALK LATER.
- YEAH. YOU EXCITED
ABOUT THE PARTY?
- I ACTUALLY MIGHT EVEN JUST
SKIP THAT.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THIS PARTY IS ESSENTIAL
FOR THE STOCKHOLDERS TO SEE.
I MEAN, WE GOTTA SHOW THEM
HOW CLOSE THIS FAMILY REALLY IS.
narrator: THIS WAS AS GOOD
AN OPENING
AS GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS GOING TO GET.
- MAEBY AND I MADE OUT.
- SORRY?
- ME TOO.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN, SON?
YOU KISSED?
- EVEN A LITTLE MORE THAN THAT.
[crowd cheering]
I THOUGHT SHE WASN'T
MY REAL COUSIN.
BUT THEN UNCLE TOBIAS SHOWED US
THESE REALLY ROUGH PICTURES
THAT PROVED THAT SHE WAS REALLY
AUNT LINDSAY'S DAUGHTER.
I JUST FEEL LIKE I CAN'T BE
AROUND HER OR AUNT LINDSAY.
THEY WERE REALLY
ROUGH PICTURES.
- NO, I REMEMBER
THEIR BIRTH ANNOUNCEMENT
LIKE IT WAS YESTERDAY.
[crowd cheering]
- I MEAN, I KNOW IT'S WRONG,
YOU KNOW,
BUT MY FEELINGS ARE REAL,
EVEN IF IT WAS A MISTAKE.
- WELL, OBVIOUSLY,
ACTING ON THOSE FEELINGS
IS NOT AN OPTION.
SHE'S A BLOOD RELATIVE.
- I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN THE BLOOD.
- HOW LONG HAS THIS
BEEN GOING ON?
- I DON'T KNOW--53 WEEKS?
I CAN'T BE AROUND HER
WITH THESE FEELINGS ANYMORE,
AND THAT'S WHY I'M NOT
GOING TO THIS PARTY.
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL MADE
ANOTHER COMPROMISE OF HIS VALUES
FOR THE SAKE OF THE BUSINESS.
- WHATEVER HAPPENED TO THAT ANN
WE WERE BOTH SO CRAZY ABOUT?
YOU KNOW, MAYBE YOU COULD
BRING HER TO THE PARTY.
YEAH, ANN IS THE GIRL
FOR US.
narrator: MICHAEL'S SISTER,
MEANWHILE,
WAS DOING SOME
SELLING OUT OF HER OWN.
- I'M NOT GOING TO SELL
MY FIVE PERCENT,
EVEN THOUGH
YOU HAVEN'T MADE AN OFFER.
WHICH WOULD BE HOW MUCH,
BY THE WAY?
- FIVE PERCENT?
LUCILLE ACTUALLY GAVE YOU LESS
THAN HER NATURAL CHILDREN.
- I HOPE THAT'S NOT A CRACK
ABOUT MY HAIR COLOR, LIPS,
FOREHEAD, NOSE, AND TEETH.
BECAUSE AT LEAST I'M NOT WEARING
A RAYON SWEATER SET ON MY FACE.
- IT'S ALPACA ACTUALLY.
CRUELTY-FREE.
REALLY NARROWS YOUR CHOICES.
BUT THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT
WHEN I SAID "NATURAL CHILD."
- WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE SAYING I'M ADOPTED?
- I'M SORRY.
I THOUGHT YOU KNEW.
HAVE I UPSET YOU?
- ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THIS IS THE HAPPIEST I'VE BEEN
SINCE THE DAY I GOT MY NEW NOSE.
I'M NOT A BLUTH.
- YOU WERE ALMOST A SITWELL.
BUT 37 YEARS AGO, THE BLUTHS
ADOPTED YOU OUT FROM UNDER US.
SO WE SAID GOOD-BYE
TO YOU,
OUR DARLING,
LITTLE THREE-YEAR-OLD.
- UH, WAIT, THREE-YEAR-OLD?
YOU SAID IT WAS 37 YEARS AGO.
- OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
HEY, WE SHOULD DO SOMETHING
FOR YOUR 40th NEXT WEEK.
narrator: THIS PART OF THE NEWS
LINDSAY DIDN'T TAKE THAT WELL.
- LET ME [bleep]
GET YOUR [bleep]
- BE GENTLE.
SHE'S ALMOST 40.
narrator: MAEBY, MEANWHILE, HAD
RETURNED TO TANTAMOUNT STUDIOS,
WHERE THE WORD WAS
SHE WAS TO BE REPLACED,
WHEN IT WAS DISCOVERED
SHE WAS NOT THE AGE
SHE CLAIMED TO BE.
- PLEASE DON'T FIRE ME.
- FIRE YOU?
ARE YOU KIDDING?
I'VE ALREADY GOTTEN 10 REQUESTS
FOR THE TV RIGHTS TO YOUR STORY.
YOU GOTTA GET YOUR FAMILY
TO SIGN THE RELEASE PAPERS.
THIS IS THE BIGGEST THING
TO HAPPEN
SINCE UNIPROD
HIRED THAT WEE-BRAIN
TO RUN DRAMA DEVELOPMENT.
narrator: MICHAEL HAD
COMPROMISED HIS MORALS
AND WAS HAVING TROUBLE
SLEEPING.
OF COURSE, SOME OF THAT
WAS LINDSAY.
- ARE YOU DRUNK?
- A LITTLE.
WE NEED TO TALK.
- YEAH, I'LL SAY.
ARE YOU AWARE
THAT YOUR DAUGHTER
AND MY SON
HAVE BEEN GETTING PHYSICAL?
I MEAN, CAN YOU IMAGINE
ANYTHING MORE INAPPROPRIATE?
HEY, I GUESS YOU CAN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I'M NOT YOUR SISTER.
- WHAT? HEY, LINDSAY.
- I'M ADOPTED.
AND I'M THREE YEARS OLDER.
- THERE MUST BE SOME MISTAKE.
- NO, MOM CONFIRMED IT.
AND I KNOW YOU'VE ALWAYS
FOUND ME ATTRACTIVE.
YOU'VE BEEN TELLING ME THAT
FOR THE LAST 40 YEARS.
- PLEASE, LINDSAY,
THIS IS CRAZY.
IF I DON'T GET DIVORCED AND
REMARRIED IN THE NEXT MONTH,
I'M GONNA SELL THOSE SHARES,
AND I'M GONNA CASH OUT.
SO WHAT DO YOU SAY?
narrator: BUT EVEN MICHAEL
COULDN'T SELL OUT THAT MUCH.
- I'M JUST NOT
THAT INTO OLDER WOMEN.
- YOU BASTARD!
- AAH!
narrator: MICHAEL HAD JUST FOUND
OUT HIS SISTER WAS ADOPTED.
AND THE NEXT MORNING,
HE AWOKE TO A WORSE SURPRISE.
- OH, COME ON!
- WELL, I CAN'T SLEEP
IN THE SAME ROOM AS HER.
SHE WANTS OUT OF
THIS MARRIAGE, FINE.
I'M AFRAID I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO SELL THE BLUTH SHARES
AND MOVE ON.
- YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
- THEY'RE MY SHARES.
- NO, I MEAN, YOU CAN'T
SPOON ME LIKE THAT.
WE NEED A NEW VENUE
FOR THE SHAREHOLDERS' PARTY,
AND IT CANNOT BE A BOAT.
NOW, IF YOU CAN FIND SOMETHING,
MAYBE I CAN FUDGE THE BOOKS.
GET YOU A BLUTH COMPANY
SALARY, HUH?
MAYBE CALL YOU
AN EVENTS COORDINATOR.
- CAN WE JUST LAY HERE
FOR A SECOND
WHILE I THINK ABOUT IT?
narrator: MICHAEL WAS MAKING
COMPROMISES ALL OVER THE PLACE.
- SURE.
- I'LL DO IT.
- SOUNDS GREAT.
narrator: SOON,
GEORGE MICHAEL WENT TO ANN'S
TO TRY TO WIN HER BACK.
BUT HER UNCLE PAUL TOLD HIM
THAT ANN HAD MOVED IN
WITH HER BOYFRIEND.
HE ALSO MENTIONED
THAT WE ALL ONLY HAD
THREE MORE WEEKS ON EARTH,
AND THAT FOSSILS
WERE JUST SOMETHING
THE JEWS BURIED IN 1924.
AND SO, FEELING THAT
HE COULDN'T GO HOME,
GEORGE MICHAEL DECIDED TO SEEK
OUT HIS OWN CREEPY UNCLE.
AND MICHAEL CONFRONTED HIS
MOTHER ABOUT THE ADOPTION.
- LOOK, SHE WAS BETTER OFF
WITH US.
HE WANTED
TO CALL HER NELLIE.
- OF COURSE. LINDSAY IS THE
NELLIE FROM THE PHOTO.
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST TELL PEOPLE
THAT SHE WAS ADOPTED?
- ADOPTING A CHILD
WE DIDN'T WANT
JUST TO STICK IT
TO A COMPETITOR?
OH, THAT WOULD
MAKE US LOOK GREAT.
- YOU'RE RIGHT, MOM.
PEOPLE WOULD HAVE TWISTED
THAT STORY TO MAKE YOU LOOK BAD.
- I DON'T SEE
WHAT THE BIG DEAL IS.
WE LOVED HER JUST AS MUCH
AS ANY OF YOU NORMAL KIDS.
MORE THAN GOB.
- THE BIG DEAL, MOM, IS THAT THE
FAMILY IS FALLING APART.
THEY'RE TRYING TO SELL THEIR
STOCK, AND I CAN'T PROMISE YOU
THAT I CAN KEEP EVERYONE
TOGETHER UNTIL THE PARTY.
- WE'LL PAY THEM OFF.
WE'LL CALL IT
AN ACCRUED CASH DIVIDEND.
BUT THEY WON'T GET THEIR MONEY
UNTIL THEY SIGN A DOCUMENT
AT THE PARTY
PROMISING NOT TO SELL
FOR 10 YEARS.
- SO IT'S EMBEZZLEMENT,
BRIBERY, AND CONSPIRACY?
- AND A WHOLE LOT
OF LOVE.
- ALL RIGHT, AND PERJURY.
- OH, MICHAEL.
- HEY. OH!
- I BOOKED A PERFECT LOCATION
AND SOME WONDERFUL PERFORMERS
FOR THE PARTY.
WE'RE HAVING IT
AT THE QUEEN MARY.
- [gasps] QUEEN MARY?
THAT'S A SHIP.
- OH, NO, NO, NO. IT'S A CHAIN
OF POPULAR NIGHTCLUBS.
ALTHOUGH I HAVEN'T BEEN
TO THIS PARTICULAR LOCATION.
IT'S ON THE LONG BEACH HARBOR.
- THAT'S THE SHIP.
- BUSTER, DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
THEY'VE ACTUALLY WELDED IT
TO THE DOCK.
- ALTHOUGH, PERHAPS
I SHOULD CALL THE HOT COPS,
AND TELL THEM TO COME UP
WITH SOMETHING
MORE NAUTICALLY THEMED.
HOT SAILORS.
BETTER YET, HOT SE--
- I LIKE HOT SAILORS.
- MM, ME TOO.
narrator: AND GEORGE MICHAEL
WAS ABOUT TO COME ACROSS
A HOT SEAMAN OF HIS OWN.
- UNCLE GOB?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
HOW'D YOU FIND ME?
- MY DAD SAID THAT
YOU WERE LIVING DOWN HERE
WITH YOUR GIRLFRIEND.
- YOU KNOW ABOUT HER?
- WHO?
- ANN.
- HER?
- narrator:
GOB HAD BEEN DATING ANN
SINCE HE AWARDED HER THIRD PLACE
IN AN INNER BEAUTY PAGEANT.
SINCE THEN, ANN AND HER FRIENDS
TRIED TO TEACH GOB
ABOUT THE HOLY TRINITY.
- WHAT? I THOUGHT THAT'S WHAT
ALL YOU GUYS LIVED FOR.
narrator: WHILE GOB DEBASED
EVERYTHING THEY BELIEVED IN.
- WHAT ABOUT YOU, YOU GAME?
- IT'S REALLY NOT THAT BIG
OF A DEAL, GEORGE MICHAEL.
I'M 18 NOW.
AND BESIDES WE REALLY HAVEN'T
EVEN DONE ANYTHING.
- PRACTICALLY NOTHING.
[crowd cheering]
BUT WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
THE GIRL OBVIOUSLY NEEDS A MAN.
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
GEORGE MICHAEL BECAME ONE.
ANN WAS UPSET.
- [screaming]
narrator: AS WAS BUSTER
WHEN HE SAW THE SHIP
WHERE THE PARTY WAS TO BE HELD.
- [screaming]
narrator: AND SO MICHAEL
ACCEPTED HIS CONGRATULATIONS,
ALL THE WHILE
LOOKING FOR HIS SON.
AND BUSTER WAS APPROACHED
BY HIS LOVING FATHER.
DO YOU THINK THERE'S ANY CHANCE
THIS SHIP COULD BREAK AWAY
FROM THE DOCK?
- WE'RE ON A SHIP?
- AH--
narrator: AND MAEBY WAS TRYING
TO GET THE FAMILY TO SIGN AWAY
THE TV RIGHTS
TO THEIR LIFE STORIES.
- TV IS NOT AS GOOD AS IT USED
TO BE, HUH, UNCLE BUSTER?
BUT YOU COULD HELP ME OUT
BY SIGNING MY PETITION
TO MAKE IT BETTER.
- OH, I KIND OF LIKE
"SKATING WITH CELEBRITIES."
EXCUSE ME.
narrator: LUCILLE WAS
TRYING TO GET SIGNATURES TOO.
- SIGN HERE THAT YOU WON'T SELL.
- OH, I DON'T NEED
TO SELL, LUCILLE,
BECAUSE NOW I KNOW
THAT WE'RE NOT RELATED,
I'M GOING TO MARRY MICHAEL.
- I ALWAYS SAW HIM
WITH A YOUNGER GIRL.
narrator:
AND GOB, ANGRY AT MICHAEL
FOR SENDING HIS SON
TO THE DOCKS--
- NOT RELATED?
narrator: WENT INTO A KIND OF
KNEE-JERK REVENGE MODE.
- WHY GO FOR THE BEST
WHEN YOU CAN GO FOR THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE
WITH A YOUNGER MAN?
KITTY LIKES TO SCRATCH.
OH, GOD! MOM! MOM!
[laughing]
- TAKE THESE FORMS
TO EVERYONE IN THE FAMILY
AND PROMISE THEM A HUNDRED GRAND
IF THEY SIGN.
narrator: THAT'S HOW MAEBY
FOUND A WAY TO GET SIGNATURES
ON HER RELEASE FORMS.
- WELL, THAT WAS A FREEBIE.
narrator: AND SOON, THE CROWD
GATHERED TO HEAR MICHAEL.
- I JUST WANNA SAY HOW MUCH THIS
FAMILY REALLY MEANS TO ME.
MY FATHER HAS ALWAYS
BEEN THERE FOR ME.
- HE'S A GREAT MAN.
[all laughing]
- MY BROTHER GOB, WHO I KNOW
WOULD NEVER DO ANYTHING
TO HURT ANYONE
IN THIS FAMILY.
narrator: EXCEPT FOR DATING
HIS NEPHEW'S GIRLFRIEND
AND HITTING ON
HIS ADOPTED SISTER.
- BUSTER, WHO FACED HIS BIGGEST
FEAR TO BE HERE TODAY--
- SECOND BIGGEST.
- AND MY SISTER, LINDSAY.
YES, SHE IS MY SISTER,
NO MATTER WHAT ANY PIECE
OF PAPER SAYS.
LINDSAY AND HER HUSBAND,
TOBIAS, YOU KNOW,
DEEP DOWN, THEY BOTH LOVE
EACH OTHER VERY, VERY MUCH.
MOST OF ALL, MY MOTHER,
WHO HAS ALWAYS BELIEVED IN ME.
THREE YEARS AGO
I MADE A CHOICE--
[clears throat]
I MADE A CHOICE
TO KEEP THIS FAMILY TOGETHER--
narrator: AND THAT'S WHEN
MICHAEL FINALLY CRIED.
- TODAY, IT LOOKS LIKE
I SUCCEEDED.
narrator:
IT WASN'T EXACTLY A TURN-ON.
[applause]
- WHOO [bleep] BABY.
- LOOKS LIKE GEORGE MICHAEL
GOT HIS MOM BACK TODAY, HUH?
- YEAH, WELL, WHERE IS
GEORGE MICHAEL, BY THE WAY?
- HE CAME BY THE YACHT.
GAVE ME THIS SHINER.
- HE HIT YOU?
WHAT FOR?
- YOU KNOW TEENAGERS.
PROBABLY LASHING OUT AT YOU
BECAUSE OF WHO I'M DATING.
- WHO ARE YOU DATING?
- ANN.
- HER?
- DON'T WORRY.
I DIDN'T FIGHT BACK OR ANYTHING.
I WAS, LIKE,
"OH, NO, TAKE THE YACHT.
PLEASE DON'T HURT ME."
JUST BUILD UP
THE LITTLE GUY'S SELF-ESTEEM.
- THE YACHT?
OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE, GOB.
I GOTTA GET OFF THIS SHIP.
MOM, GEORGE MICHAEL
TOOK OFF IN GOB'S YACHT.
I GOTTA GO FIND HIM.
- WELL, YOU CAN'T GO NOW.
THAT'S NOT GOING TO LOOK GOOD
IN FRONT OF THE INVESTORS.
- MOM, THIS IS IMPORTANT, OKAY?
- MICHAEL!
THIS COMPANY
IS IMPORTANT.
narrator: IT WAS AT THAT MOMENT
THAT MICHAEL REALIZED
HOW MUCH HE'D SOLD OUT.
- NEVER SEEN A C.E.O.
CRY LIKE THAT BEFORE,
EXCEPT AT HIS SENTENCING.
THAT'S WHO YOU'RE
PUTTING IN CHARGE?
- I'VE MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
WILL YOU TAKE THE COMPANY
FOR 20% ABOVE MARKET?
- TEN, AND I'LL TAKE THE COMPANY
OFF YOUR HANDS RIGHT NOW.
- FIFTEEN AND I'LL
THROW IN NELLIE.
- SHE'S 40.
- TWELVE.
narrator: MEANWHILE, MICHAEL
SEARCHED THE HARBOR
AND SPOTTED THE YACHT.
AND GOB NOTICED
SOMETHING TOO.
- ARE THOSE POLICE BOATS?
- OH, MY GOD,
IT'S THE S.E.C.
- THEY STILL HAVE BOATS?
- PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
- DID YOU DO THIS?
- NO. BUT I CAN'T HELP BUT ENJOY
THE IRONY
THAT YOU MIGHT BE
LOSING THREE YEARS OF YOUR LIFE.
- AH, THIS IS WHY THEY DROPPED
THOSE OTHER CHARGES.
YOU GAVE ME UP, GEORGE.
- GEORGE? I'M NOT GEORGE.
GEORGE INVITED ME.
OH, STUPID.
OSCAR, WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO
LEARN
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS FREE SHRIMP?
- WELL, I KNOW IT WAS SOMEONE
IN THIS FAMILY.
- OR SOMEONE WHO USED TO BE.
- ANNYONG?
- BUT MY REAL NAME IS...HELLO.
- HELLO?
- WHAT THE HELL
DID YOU DO THIS FOR?
- BECAUSE MY GRANDFATHER
VOWED ONE DAY
HE WOULD GET EVEN FOR BANANA
STAND YOU STOLE FROM HIM.
narrator: IT WAS TRUE.
HELLO HAD GATHERED
INFORMATION AGAINST LUCILLE...
TO AVENGE HIS GRANDFATHER.
- HEY, MAEBY EVER MENTION
MY NAME?
narrator: BUT LUCILLE WAS NOT
GOING PEACEFULLY.
- YOU BOYS KNOW HOW
TO SHOVEL COAL?
narrator: I DON'T EVEN
WANNA TELL YOU
WHAT THESE GUYS
THOUGHT THAT MEANT.
AND MICHAEL CAUGHT UP
WITH HIS SON.
- GEORGE MICHAEL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- I CAN'T STAY HERE.
ANN'S MOVED ON.
MAEBY'S MY COUSIN.
WE BOTH KNOW
THAT'S NOT AN OPTION.
- BUDDY, MAEBY
IS NOT YOUR COUSIN.
- WHAT?
- YEAH, I FOUND OUT
A COUPLE DAYS AGO.
AUNT LINDSAY
WAS ADOPTED.
- WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME THIS?
- BECAUSE YOU CAN'T BE
WITH MAEBY. YOU'RE 15.
AND SO INEVITABLY,
THE RELATIONSHIP
IS GONNA FALL APART,
AND THEN WHAT DO YOU DO?
SHE MIGHT NOT BE
A BLOOD RELATIVE,
BUT SHE IS STILL FAMILY,
AND THAT'S A BOND
THAT LASTS FOREVER.
YOU DON'T WANNA
ROCK THAT BOAT.
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
narrator:
IT WAS HIS MOTHER,
WHO MOMENTS EARLIER HAD TAKEN
CONTROL OF ANOTHER QUEEN.
- FULL STEAM, BOYS!
- THIS IS DEGRADING.
I THOUGHT WE WERE GONNA STRIP.
- MOTHER!
[clanging]
- [whimpering]
[ship's horn sounds]
IT'S MOVING!
OH, MY GOD!
[screams]
narrator: AND BUSTER FACED
HIS SECOND BIGGEST FEAR.
- I CAN'T SWIM! I CAN'T SWIM!
narrator:
AND THEN HIS FIRST.
[seal barking]
- OH, COME ON!
narrator:
AND THE TWO GRAND LADIES
MADE THEIR ESCAPE TOGETHER.
- LUCILLE BLUTH,
PLEASE PULL OVER
AND STEP AWAY
FROM THE HISTORIC SHIP.
- GANGY'S TRYING
TO MAKE A BREAK FOR IT.
- WELL, I GUESS
WE SHOULD GO BACK.
FAMILY STICKS TOGETHER, HUH?
- YEAH,
ON THE OTHER HAND,
WE DO HAVE A FULL TANK OF GAS,
A HOUSE IN CABO,
AND 500 GRAND
IN CASHIER'S CHECKS.
WHAT SAY WE GIVE THEM
NO CHOICE
BUT TO KEEP THEMSELVES
ALL TOGETHER FOR A WHILE?
narrator:
IT WAS "ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT."
ON THE EPILOGUE.
MICHAEL WAKES UP
TO ANOTHER STRANGE BEDFELLOW
AFTER HIS FIRST NIGHT AT SEA.
- HOW WAS THE PARTY?
narrator:
AND MAEBY PITCHES HER TV SHOW
TO A HOLLYWOOD ICON, WHO SAYS-
- NO, I, UH--
I DON'T SEE IT AS A SERIES.
MAYBE A MOVIE.