NARRATOR:
Hollywood Boulevard at night
is the playground of the hip,
young and successful.
It was into this world that
Gob Bluth had finally arrived,
surrounded for
the first time in his life
by a group of admirers
that comprised L.A.'s
latest young elite.
There was Mark, a pop star
who had a level of fame
he could neither appreciate
nor handle.
Trout, a Southern boy who had
a Northern man's
taste in women.
J.B.J., a weekend weatherman,
all-week party boy
and a huge disappointment
to his father.
Chris K,
who was a lot like Trout,
but without the accent.
Oakwood, a studio teacher,
who might have had
his own entourage,
if his part hadn't been cut
from the pilot of
Modern Family.
And, of course, there was
the man they called Getaway.
Gob had come far in the year
since his girlfriend,
was less than an hour
from turning 18.
Let me run the clock down
on this thing.
Why don't you just go change
into something a little less...
unflattering, and... I'll, uh...
And he was getting everyone
in the mood for romance.
Guess I'll take my clothes off.
While Ann
less-unflattered herself up,
Gob had an unexpected visitor--
Ann's ex-boyfriend
George Michael,
who, as it turned out,
hadn't completely let go
of the relationship.
(shrieking)
You're lucky that I'm chasing
after our girlfriend,
or I'd have to flatten you!
Whew! Way to plant, Ann.
You told me George Michael
knew about us.
Well, he does now,
my darling plant.
Ann.
And...
after I dazzle everyone tonight
on the Queen Mary,
my magic career will take off
as surely as there's a mouse
behind your ear.
(Ann screams)
Well, as surely as there's
a mouse behind your ear.
(Ann screams)
-Mouse behind...
-(Ann screams)
Okay, you are like
the only person I know
who doesn't just love magic.
A poll would confirm
she was far from alone.
BEARD:
...for the fifth year in a row,
your least favorite
entertainers are...
magicians.
A close second,
talk show side-kicks.
-Hmph!
-(bleep)
-you, too, America.
-...'cause I quit.
Well, you have to make things
right with George Michael,
otherwise you don't get
to fourth base.
Of course, Ann's concept
of fourth base...
...was very different
than Gob's.
But you have to promise me
you'll always be faithful.
Faithful?
Of course I can be faithful.
Until tonight, when we're
together, you know...
Oh! Until tonight!
Well, of course I can be
faithful-- don't be stupid.
You think I can't
keep it in my pants
in front of a bunch of
doggy old women and my family?
Don't be stupid.
Who am I gonna hit on, stupid?
My sister? Lindsay?
Don't be stupid.
She's my sister; that's gross.
Now...
you...
have got some mice
to scoop out of the sea.
Now the story of a family
whose future
was abruptly canceled,
and the one son
who had no choice
but to keep himself together.
It's Gob's
Arrested Development.
NARRATOR: On the day
of the Queen Mary party,
Gob remained faithful to Ann,
even in the face
of tremendous temptation.
-Unrelated.
-But there would be
-(screaming)
-no career-making magic show.
It seemed the only "her"
Gob would be
getting off that day
was the Queen Mary.
But then the Queen
changed course,
heading back to shore
before crashing into the jetty
and leaving most
of its occupants all wet.
I want all of these
on the insurance form, okay?
These are all part of an act
I was going to do.
Two drowned white doves,
for "flowers to doves."
This was a rabbit, for "doves to
rabbit"-- also drowned.
These were mice...
TOBIAS:
For "rabbit to mice."
No, that can't be done.
No, these were
part of a something
I called "Mice-a-laneous."
"Mouse in purse."
"Mouse in drink."
"Here's a mouse, now it's gone."
How'd he do dat?
But it was another man that Gob
needed to make things
right with...
George Michael...
...if he was ever going
to deflower Ann Veal.
Uncle Gob.
Are we good?
(George Michael sighs)
(voice breaking):
No.
No, how could we possibly be?
But... but are we, are we good?
No!
You stole my girlfriend.
That's a tough thing,
and, you know,
sometimes you have to ask
yourself: "Are we good?"
Is it over between you guys?
Oh, no.
But are we good?
I don't know what you want
to hear from me, Uncle Gob.
-I mean, yes, we are good...
-There it is!
There it is!
Ah, from a nephew to his uncle,
and just the "yes,"
the much-vaunted "yes,"
that he gets.
Look at you, full of "yes."
Look at how much "yes"
is in you!
I knew it! I knew I'd get
that "yes" from you.
Look who got a "yes"!
Got my "yes."
And Gob realized that there was
finally nothing
standing in the way
of a loving,
committed relationship
with Ann.
("The Sound Of Silence"
intro playing)
♪ Hello, darkness,
my old friend ♪
♪ I've come to talk with... ♪
So, that night,
as he broke into her house
to break up with her...
(startled shout)
-(yells)
-Gob...!
For a second, I thought
that was a real guy.
So, listen, I talked to George
Michael and everything's cool.
I need to tell you something,
though.
I've been doing some thinking
and I... I just don't...
But as she unzipped
her pajamas,
it reminded him
of past situations
which he'd successfully
been aroused.
Well, I could wait till after.
(light switch clicks)
And later, Gob once again tried
to find a compassionate way
to end the relationship.
So how did you like your egg?
I said you were fine.
So, was there something you
wanted to talk about
when you came in through
my window?
Gob, what is it?
What... what... is it?
I... (laughs) You...
It's the-the-the-the-the...
the-the questions...
you ask so many...
of these, of these, of these,
these-these questions
that-that-that-that you
keeping asking for me...
for-for-for-for...
should-should-should...
should I, should I, should I?
Should-should-should the,
should the, should the,
should-should the guy,
should the guy,
should the guy in the...
in the $32... in the $32 pink...
bath-bath-bath-bath...
Should-should-should-should...
should the girl
in the $6,000 tuxedo...
Gob was uncomfortable
with the question.
...should-should-should...
in the $32...
in the $3,400... should the guy,
come on... come on...
-Let's, let's, let's...
-Come on...
(sobbing):
...come on, come on...
Gob! Calm down!
Listen, we had
a great night together.
I understand if you need
your freedom.
Well... marry me.
Yes, I'll...
yes, I'll marry you, Gob!
Of course, Gob meant it
in the showbizzy way
his niece had always used
when she was accused
of being too young.
What, are you, like, 15?
-Marry me! -...marry me!
-...marry me!
-And may I add: marry me.
-...marry me.
But like many evangelicals,
Ann took it literally.
I'm getting married!
(family screaming happily,
laughing)
Gob was surrounded
by unconditional love
from a family,
for the first time in his life.
("The Sound Of Silence"
intro playing)
♪ Hello, darkness,
my old friend... ♪
GOB:
I've made a huge mistake.
Gob shared his happy news
at a meeting with his family.
I'm sure Gob helped himself
to the money.
Hey, I got mouths to feed.
Mouths?
Mouth.
Her.
Oh, hey, mouth.
I didn't see you sitting there.
We rode up
in the elevator together.
I'm blanking.
Yeah, me and Blank are getting
the old Christian magic act
back together.
I mean, you don't expect people
to actually believe
that I'm Jesus,
if I'm walking around in rags.
You're resurrecting
that mumbo-jumbo?
Look, everybody's got a gimmick.
Tony Wonder's making a fortune
with that gay magician act.
Gob's long-time nemesis
had come out of the closet
and used it to great advantage
in his act.
Besides, I have to do something
for the wedding.
MICHAEL:
Who's getting married?
Her!
Who's marrying her?
Me.
-Did I not open with that?
-You sure didn't.
Yeah, I'm getting married!
(gasping)
I didn't want
to make a big deal about it.
-You haven't.
-Well, my wedding's
going to be religious-y and epic
and expensive,
which is why I need more of that
stimmy-mummy.
Thanks, Mike.
And perhaps it was
all the talk of spirituality
that led to this.
(applause)
And welcome to
And As It Is Such, So Also
As Such Is It Unto You.
Excuse me, Father Marsala,
I hate to interrupt,
but I am so excited today.
My lovely Ann...
-Who?
-My daughter.
Oh. I didn't know
you had a daughter.
You've met her several times.
Oh.
She's sitting right next to you.
Oh!
That's why she's there.
I thought you were Hair.
Hair?
No, she's my daughter,
and she's getting married!
To this good man.
(applause)
Well, and as it is such,
so also as such is it
unto you, young man.
You got it.
Unto you, as well...
dear f... heavenly fathers.
MARSALA: Well, we have
a really great show today
surrounding the Scriptures...
GOB:
We have an announcement to make.
I have an announcement to make:
that we would like to televise
our marriage, here on this show.
-(applause)
-My goodness.
Oh, um... we hadn't heard of it.
Did you...?
Well, no, but that's... no...
What an idea. I think...
Well, this show is about
the spirit of inclusion,
-so I would love to say...
-Well, great!
Then I, too,
have an announcement to make!
At our wedding,
I will be performing
one of my
famous magical illusions.
That once your eyes
have beholden it,
you will put no god before me,
because of its spectacularity.
And, of course, I only propose
to do this out of love for...
ANN:
Ann.
And... God.
Love for and God.
Let me pray.
Dearest beloved gods...
Gob was feeling bolder,
which was perhaps why
Michael returned home
to find this.
GOB:
And yea, as if to be arisen
the third or fourth day with all
the magic of Jesus Christ!
MICHAEL: Sorry.
Wasn't on there too good.
-(Gob grunting, groaning)
-You okay?
Yeah, it's just part of my...
illusion for the wedding.
Yeah, what's the illusion?
That you actually
love the bride?
Hey...
that's good patter.
'Cause I need people to root
for the Jesus character.
I don't remember
a biblical passage where Jesus
came out of a boulder--
is it in there?
Oh, no, no, no,
the boulder's my escape plan.
They think I'm somewhere else.
I'm actually in the boulder.
But I didn't come here to talk
-about my magic act, Michael.
-Okay.
I came to ask you
to be my best man...
slash-assistant.
And then we'll walk through
the act later, of course.
-I mean, not now.
-No, we're not going to,
'cause you know,
I'm out of the family.
Did you not get that
when I announced it
over at Mom's place?
I feel like I was out
of the room at that point.
I am done with this family.
I hope you've saved some money
'cause you...
♪ Hello, darkness,
my old friend... ♪
MICHAEL:
Well, the gist of it was:
"You know what?
I'm done with this family.
"I hope you saved your money
'cause you're
going to need
every last dime now."
Maybe you could be a centurion,
kind of standing over
where they think that I'll be.
I'm not going to be in the act.
Might be a great promotion
for the Bluth Company.
No, Bluth Company's done.
I started my own company:
Michael B. Company.
I have a bee company.
You stole my idea?
Uh-uh, I did not steal your...
We sell...
It would take hours.
How's that going, by the way?
Uh, not so good.
I've been keeping the bees
in my apartment.
I was using my magic smoke
on them.
And my bees are dropping
like flies,
and I need them to fly
like bees.
And so I've got them out
at a bee hospital,
which is not cheap,
which is another reason
I need to be a famous magician.
Yeah, well, listen,
you're with my son's ex,
so I can't support the wedding.
What if I don't actually
get married?
I don't think you'd need
a best man, then, right?
No, I guess, at that point,
it'd really be more...
assistant.
Is this an escape act?
-Are you running again?
-What do you want from me?
Marriage is a lot of pressure,
and she's not into it.
Meanwhile, I'm working out
like crazy,
my diet has become insane,
and this Jesus character--
I mean, he was shredded.
Meanwhile, we have sex one time,
and then she's just,
you know, over it.
Lets herself go.
Her stomach's out to here.
You know, your whole life
is an escape act,
and this girl seems
like she really likes you.
Why don't you just try
to work it out
and just stop running...?
Yeah, I know you're
in the boulder.
GOB:
But how'd I get in the boulder?
NARRATOR:
And on the day of the wedding,
even though Gob
didn't take it seriously,
he was a little hurt
to discover
no one else
in his family did, either.
ANN:
I know it's bad luck for you
to see me in my gown
before the wedding.
Well, hopefully I haven't.
You're angry.
Why? Because none of my family
has shown up
and the only person I recognize
out there is Tony Wonder,
who's only shown up
hoping that I'd fail?
I don't know what
your surprise trick is, but...
I know it's going to be great.
And as for your family...
you have a new family now.
(chuckles)
I don't want these.
-Tobias!
-Gob.
-Thanks for coming.
-Oh, how could I not?
I'm playing
Roman Centurion Number Two.
-What are you playing?
-I'm the groom.
I didn't know there
was a groom part.
You know, Betty
at And As It Is Such,
So Also As Such
Is It Unto You casting
told me this was all biblical.
Wait, you're not here
for the wedding?
Well, thank you very much
for your vote of confidence.
I'll have you know I've worked
for the Miracle Network
a number of times.
ANNOUNCER:
Coming up next:
Father Marsala's
searing docudrama,
John the Baptist.
Then the antiabortion drama,
Embryo Dan: It Would Have Been
a Wonderful Life.
And later,
break out the bagels.
It's time for Father M's
lighthearted comedy,
-A Jew Came to Dinner.
-TOBIAS: I hate to be
the guy who quotes
his own reviews,
but His Word magazine...
called my Jew "pitiful."
NARRATOR:
But soon,
the wedding began.
PASTOR VEAL:
So, it truly is a blessed day.
I believe that we
are all blessed,
uh, to be gathering here
at the Church
of the Holy Eternal Rapture.
Uh, we have almost arrived
at that glorious moment
where we join together
these two very special people,
but first, my almost son-in-law
has something he'd like
to share with all of us,
so, um...
ladies and gentlemen, uh,
please enjoy a magical...
uh, trick.
Thanks for that killer intro.
It's true,
this is a magical trick.
If what Jesus did was a trick.
(crowd gasping)
I say it wasn't.
(laughter, applause)
It was an illusion.
(crowd gasping softly)
TOBIAS:
Ooh, they did not like that one.
I don't take notes from you,
Centurion Number Two.
Just turn this thing around.
I am not the real Jesus.
I am the Amazing Jesus!
No? I thought that that
would be up your... alley.
Yes, the real Jesus
came off the cross
and went into his cave...
a dead man.
NARRATOR:
And Gob's escape boulder
was wheeled up to the trick.
But was he crazy enough
to do it... handcuffed?
Handcuff the King of the Jews!
GOB:
You don't have words here...
Pastor Veal, if you don't mind,
please go up into the cave
and assure everyone
that there's no way to escape:
no trapdoors,
no secret compartments,
no way to get out.
Thank you very...
Pastor Veal, let me remind you
that you are in a church
in front of your daughter,
your congregation, God.
You cannot tell a lie.
Right, nothing
out of the ordinary?
-No, I-I didn't see anything.
-Yes.
Jesus went into the cave,
and he arose three days later.
But I'm not going to lock myself
in the cave
for three days
before this wedding ceremony.
No, no. No, no, no.
I plan on beating his record
by two full weeks!
(dramatic music playing)
Into the cave with you!
GOB: No, I said don't underline
the "you" in that.
NARRATOR: Unfortunately,
Gob was not able to open
the secret compartment that
contained the handcuff key.
It's not going to work. Okay,
uh, this isn't going to work.
Let's do...
let's do mouse in drink.
Let's do mouse in drink.
Just get these people
some drinks.
We'll just get a mouse.
No, no, no. No, no, no,
you know not what you do!
But it very clearly said
in the centurions' script
to ignore
the magician's protests,
which meant that,
still handcuffed...
But if my hands are handcuffed,
I'll never...
...Gob was unable
to break his fall
and was therefore
knocked unconscious.
And as the Gob dummy
was sealed inside the cave,
the real Gob's fate
was sealed, as well.
Well, I guess...
we'll wait two weeks...
...and see if he's in there.
Is that okay with you, Ann?
He's not coming back.
NARRATOR: Gob was stuck
inside a fake boulder in
-the parking lot of a church,
-GOB (weakly): Hey, kids.
while inside the church,
the daily routine
-proceeded as usual
-I-18.
-and the anticipation grew
to a fevered pitch.
-I-18.
11 exciting days, um,
although nothing's
really happened.
Day 11.
Once he gets out,
it's going to be
a beautiful, beautiful wedding.
He's not coming back.
But it was Betty
from And As It Is Such,
So Also As Such Is It Unto You
that would render Gob's
-escape act a disaster.
-You got to get rid of this
thing.
-I got Mrs. Murray's trailer
here.
-I guess, if he comes back
from the dead,
we could just get a stepladder.
-Guys, this, too.
-And a hoarse,
weakened Gob was unable
to stop them
as the boulder was shipped
to a storage unit in Tustin.
Although a keen eye could see
that Gob was alive
but not well.
And that's why this
particular chair was empty
at the trial of Lucille Bluth.
Well, I can't thank you
all enough for returning...
At the end of two weeks,
the big day
-finally arrived... again.
-So let's count down.
Let's have some fun,
uh, from five, four...
-three, two, one.
-The dead will walk amongst us.
No, he shan't,
for he-eth not here.
-I knew it.
-TOBIAS: Oh, there's a note.
"If I have not yet returned,
I am in the Rapture."
Oh, and then it says,
"Love each other."
MRS. VEAL: What does he think
we've been doing?
I loaned him $1,000.
Gob didn't fare much better
than the bride,
finally being discovered
on an episode
of the auction reality show...
MAN:
Moment of truth, people.
It's a masker.
Jesus, there's a man in there.
(auctioneer coughing,
speaking indistinctly)
-Let's get the bidding started
at a hundred dollars.
Anybody?
-(hissing)
-Nope.
He's hissing.
NARRATOR:
After a week in the hospital,
Gob was happy to finally see
a familiar shape.
You humiliated me.
You made a mockery
of my religion
and you ruined our wedding.
Our first fight,
and like all fights,
you're a little right,
I'm a little right.
I sold your cave on Craigslist.
So it was all worth it.
We have money to start
our life together.
Now we have our nest, egg-- Ann.
Now we have our, our nest, Ann.
I'm leaving you, Gob.
I don't love you anymore.
I feel sorry for you, and
you're gonna be alone forever
unless you let the Holy Ghost
inside you.
(laughing):
The, the Holy...
(stammering)
You know what?
I hope you read this.
NARRATOR: And maybe it was
the fact that he had nothing
in his system
but two weeks of candy vines,
but it did get through to him.
Steve.
It's me. Uh, I-I wanted
to let you know
that I am... I'm-I'm ready to...
to... to...
let the son of Gob enfold me.
Have you been to the club And,
owned by Jeremy "Pivan"?
I'm gonna be there tonight
about 8:00.
Maybe you could join me,
I don't...
Obviously it's, it's me,
your fa...
(beep)
Nah, he got it.
Okay.
NARRATOR:
Gob was waiting to meet his son
at a bar and feeling
a little vulnerable.
Lost my wife, lost my career.
When I was in that storage unit
at the bottom of that rock,
it was like I hit...
-Rock bottom?
-No, no, not that.
More like a trending
downward moment
that just-- I don't know.
Maybe I'm being tested like
that guy "Jawb" from the Bible.
-(pronounces correctly): Job.
-Yes?
Job.
Yes, sir.
-Job.
-Yeah.
-Look, I, I feel sorry
for you, Pops.
-Hey, pal,
I'm not that much older
than you, guy.
-(chuckles)
-Nah, I'm just here,
I'm looking for my son.
I'm trying to get some cash
out of him, actually.
You, you have another son?
(Steve laughing)
I have a brother?
Oh, man.
Yes, Steve.
Yeah.
-What's his name?
-Dave.
Oh, Dave Holt.
-Yeah, Dave Holt.
-Yes.
NARRATOR: Yes, Gob
had been speaking to his son
for an hour and a half.
-Wait, your mom's name is Eve?
-Yeah.
God, I (bleep) a chick
named Eve once.
Biggest mistake of my life.
NARRATOR:
And perhaps it was because
Gob was inadvertently so warm
to his son that Steve
-offered him a job.
-I don't even really have a job.
Would you want
to come work with me?
I mean, I...
Are you serious?
I mean, I'm in pest control, but
father and son.
What a great team.
It would be a great team.
I mean, I don't care.
Pest control-- I don't know.
As long as I'm not being
a pest to you, right?
-No, never.
-I mean, I'm kidding.
(Gob mumbling)
Where is your place of business?
-181...
-Manville.
Manville.
What time do you start
this pest control?
7:00 a.m.
Then I'll be there at 6:45
with two cups of coffee.
Oh, Dad, this is
the greatest day of my life.
No, this is the greatest day
of my life.
And perhaps it was because
it was such a great day...
-6:45. -6:45.
-...that Gob decided
to stay at the bar...
-6:45.
-...and show off a little.
I bet it's been a long time
since you've seen your...
-...cherry.
-I have lupus.
(spits)
Could have warned a guy.
But showing off did catch
the attention of someone.
That was the real deal, huh?
How about this?
How about you do that cherry
trick for my boy Mark Cherry?
Mark Cherry
the baby-faced singer
or Marc Cherry
the baby-faced showrunner?
Baby-faced singer--
right over there, man.
He has loved magic
ever since he was a kid.
NARRATOR: Which was two years
earlier, when Mark Cherry was
the star of a cable teen sitcom
called
Pop-A-ROTC, created by
a longtime writing veteran
of the TV show Cheers.
Soon, Mark Cherry became
a pop sensation
off his cowritten hit single
"Practice Kisses."
JOHN JR.: I found a gentleman
who is about
-to do a magic trick for you.
-No, it's an illusion.
A trick is something
a whore does for...
Do a trick and I'll pay
for your bar tab.
-Who wants a trick?
-ALL: Yeah!
(all cheering)
NARRATOR: Gob had them
in the palm of his hand.
He even got the attention
-of a still out-of-control
Rebel Alley...
-Do it again.
-I missed it.
-...who was
there doing research
-for an upcoming PSA...
-Fireball!
...she'd soon be required
to do by law.
Fire, fire!
Never yell "fire"
in a crowded place.
It's never funny.
That's always funny.
NARRATOR: And she was intrigued
by this magical man.
-Oh...
-Whoa.
That is a David Spade.
(clears throat)
Check your purse.
(gasping)
-(Gob chuckles)
-Nice.
Oh, man, paparazzo.
Oh, shoot, great.
The last thing I need is to be
seen partying with some tweens.
I'm trying to clean up my act.
Dude, network's gonna flip
if there's another drunk photo
of you.
-I know.
-We got to get you away
-from this place, okay?
-Getting away
is kind of my specialty.
I'll have us out of here
in a flash.
All right.
Let's get out of here while
they still got lighter fluid
-in their eyes.
-Go, baby.
(all laughing)
-Oh, man.
-Oh...
Nice moves, Getaway.
Oh.
Okay.
NARRATOR: Gob had been accepted
into the group,
which was bad news for Cherry's
business manager's son
Josh Abramson.
Gob actually did
end up driving down Manville
-at 6:45 a.m.
-This is it! This is...
I'll be with you in a second,
I'll be right there.
Start without me,
just start without me.
Don't worry!
He's not coming back.
NARRATOR:
Gob was living the dream,
and felt like he was
in the center of the entourage,
even though he was three away
from the center at the closest,
and it was pop star
Mark Cherry's dream.
Hey, I'm with, with the guys.
Keep the limo running, Getaway.
That's my job.
(siren chirps)
NARRATOR: The next few months
were a blur of partying...
(shouting)
...and shame.
(shouting and laughter)
But Gob had a trick
for helping him forget
the shame.
Unfortunately
it also helped him forget
that he tried to forget
the shame...
-Hey, remember me?
-and soon Gob
found himself experiencing...
Hey, I'm having myself
a little bit of a...
what, on the street,
is referred to...
-...empty bottle situation.
-...as a roofie circle...
-I won't forget this.
-...whereby a roofie
is taken the day
after a degrading event...
...too late to erase the memory
of the degrading event itself
but not too late to erase
the prior day's attempt
to erase the event.
(whistles)
-Thus, with no memory
of taking the roofie...
- Hey, remember me?
-...but the memory of the event
very much alive..
- Been a while.
Oh, I should grab a, uh... oh.
...the victim of the
roofie circle finds himself
constantly trying
to re-erase the memory...
What's with the scary guy?
-(speaking Spanish)
-Céllate.
...but only succeeds
in erasing the memory
of the attempt
to erase the memory.
Days turn into weeks,
weeks turn into months...
(laughs) What's with all
the Christmas decorations?
And what begins in shame...
-Hey, remember me?
-No, no més, no més.
-...almost always ends...
-You remember me?
-...in a Mexican hospital...
-Remember me?
-...with stage-four syphilis.
(groans)
Gob was also wearing out
his welcome
with Mark
and the other hangers-on.
See, told you I knew him.
Can I get a picture with him
to show my five-year-old?
You have a five-year-old?
My granddaughter.
-Oh, yeah, right.
-Thank you.
-The hell?
-Run, run, run.
NARRATOR: And perhaps
it was this incident...
-(bleep) Getaway.
-...that inspired Mark Cherry
to actually write
a song about Gob.
♪ Go away, Getaway,
stay away, Getaway... ♪
NARRATOR: But the lyrics were
too subtle for Gob to notice.
I know guys just like that.
NARRATOR: And as his life
in the Malibu colony
was falling apart,
he got a call
that his bee colony
wasn't doing much better
from a very much alive
Johnny Bark.
They're sick. They're going
to collapse the whole colony.
You tell him
about the sick bees?
Jesus, I just said that!
NARRATOR:
And Gob returned just in time
to catch his friends going out
for the evening without him.
Guys, hurry before he sees us.
Come on.
Hey, guys, where we going?
I-I-I'll drive, I just got to
put my sick bees in the trunk.
NARRATOR:
And perhaps this was the moment
that Gob could sense
the tide was turning.
It's my fault, guys.
I made a mistake.
(bee buzzing)
NARRATOR: In an effort to remain
popular with the gang,
Gob stopped in front of a club
to pick up some women.
GOB: Who wants to party
with Mark Cherry?
Uh, me, me, me...
That's one forget-me-now saved,
huh, fellas?
Oh, looks like we got a real
live one, and by alive, I mean
barely alive.
(clamoring)
-Take off your...
-Clothes.
We're having a good time.
We are having a great time.
-MARK: Hey, Getaway.
-Yeah.
You know what'd be really cool?
If you shut the partition.
It'd be like, uh, like a joke,
like you're our limo driver...
That would be hilarious, right?
"Oh, yes, very good,
sir, very good."
Right?
Be like, "I'm... I'm just
driving the queen of England,"
but we're still--
we're taking our clothes off.
But perhaps
if they had not excluded Gob...
DEBRIE:
You guys have anything harder?
...he could have prevented this
from happening.
Like, what's in here? You have
the good stash in here?
What are you talking about?
(bees buzzing)
(all screaming)
"A lot of traffic out here
today, Miss Daisy."
(screaming, bees buzzing)
♪ Go away, Getaway,
stay away, Getaway... ♪
NARRATOR:
On the plus side,
Gob's bees were feeling
good enough to sting again.
I see this boat and I'm like,
"Those are police boats,"
so, anyway, I'm running around
and I said, "It's not a trick,
it's an illusion..."
To the entourage, the evening
was a complete disaster.
Drunken, sick
and covered with bee stings,
they had truly hit bottom.
(chuckles)
For Gob, however,
it was an amazing night,
and he couldn't wait
to forget it.
Hmm, hmm.
Fun night.
(laughs)
A... fun night.
Fun night.
(chuckles)
NARRATOR:
The next day, Getaway awoke
without a care in the world
and snuck to the front door,
trying not to arouse the gang
he assumed would be blissfully
sleeping it off all day.
-Wake up!
-But Gob had slept through
the seven ambulances
that had arrived
after Josh Abramson had swung
by to pick up an old computer.
Nonetheless,
later that evening,
Gob arrived early at the Opies,
an award show
that honored youth
in Hollywood, to make sure
that Mark Cherry
would be well taken care of...
Where's the coconut shrimp?
...before he was scheduled
to perform.
Hey, come on,
my guys love coconut shrimp,
especially if they can get it
with a little bit of club...
NARRATOR:
It was then that Gob noticed
the presence of a competitor
from his past.
T.W.
Tony Wonder.
NARRATOR: Gob realized
that where there was glitter,
there must also be
Tony Wonder...
and that's when Gob decided
to take advantage
of an unexpected diversion
and have a little fun
by wedging shut
a panel on the podium
he knew Tony Wonder
would pop out of.
You guys want to see
a real failed magician?
You might want to get down
to the Opies tonight.
It's going to be hysterical.
NARRATOR: And that's when Gob
found out that Mark Cherry
had checked into rehab.
Well, come on, you guys,
I mean, it's just...
A little alcohol poisoning
never killed anyone.
NARRATOR: Actually, alcohol
poisoning is responsible
for over 4,000 deaths a year.
Binge drinking-- not cool.
Well, that's a drag.
I thought we were friends.
NARRATOR:
But, of course, they weren't.
MORT: But Schnoodle's
coming out now, too,
-just like Tony Wonder.
-And that's when he saw
Tony Wonder come out
of a speaker.
TONY:
I'm here, I'm queer.
And now I'm in a speaker.
-MORT: No one can stop us.
-(explosion)
NARRATOR:
It was in that pivotal moment
that Gob realized
he had lost his fiancíe,
his career, his family
and his entourage.
I have no one in my life
who cares for me.
("The Sound of Silence"
intro playing)
♪ Hello, darkness... ♪
♪ Go away, Getaway,
stay away, Getaway... ♪
Great, and now my boss
is on my ass.
♪ Get away, Getaway... ♪
NARRATOR: Gob nurses
the loss of his new family
when he gets a call
from his old one.
This is Gob.
LUCILLE (over phone):
It's your mother.
We're going to plan "B."
Go see your father
in the desert.
He wants you to prepare
to be president
-of the Bluth Company.
-Yes, finally.
I will not disappoint you, Mom.
I am the perfect person
to look out for this family.
-(horn honks)
-Whoa.
♪ Hey, I met a girl today... ♪
♪ Get away, Getaway... ♪
NARRATOR: And after collapsing
yet another colony,
Gob makes
a startling discovery...
My cave.
...and decides
to investigate...
Why didn't you open?
...only to discover
that someone had wedged shut
his secret compartment
on the day he deserted
his Christian bride.
"T."
Tony Wonder.