[narrator] On the top of a hillside,
deep in the mountains
of Shuturmurg, India,
sits a mystical retreat long sought out
by those seeking answers...
[Lindsay] Is this real?
...to the questions that define us.
I mean, is any of this real?
How do I know what's real?
You see me before you, yes?
I am real to you.
And this bag next to me,
it is as real as you or me.
[narrator] It was also known
for their bargains on designer handbags.
No, I know that one's real.
I meant the other one, the Louis Vuitton.
I don't remember Vuitton having two E's.
Lindsay Bluth had come to India
for both reasons.
That's how they do it here.
You can't go wrong.
-Best bag on the mountain.
-I love this bag. I give you 64.
-It's the best bag on the mountain!
-Lindsay's journey to the mountain top
had been brief,
by spiritual sojourn standards.
You just bought the best bag
on the mountain. Congratulations.
-Best bag on the mountain.
-It had been only weeks
since she heard the news that she wasn't
born to the family she couldn't bear.
I'm adopted? Are you kidding me?
She took that news rather well.
Hey, we should do something
for your 40th next week.
-And then heard some more that she didn't.
-[Lindsay] Get your [bleep]!
She's almost 40!
And although she had a brief moment
of comeuppance with her mother...
But I can't help but enjoy the irony
that you might be losing
three years off your life.
[narrator] She soon discovered
that Lucille was a woman
who didn't like to be comeuppanced.
And you have no right to criticize me.
At least I was able
to turn my Queen around.
-None taken.
-[man] Hi, Tobias.
You cannot say one nice thing
to your daughter, can you?
Adopted daughter.
And that's not true.
[Narrator] And perhaps that's when Lindsay
realized her mother would never accept her
as one of her own.
[man] Can I have
the Bluth family over here, please?
And over here,
the victims of the Bluth family?
[narrator] And took her first steps away
from the Bluth family.
Lindsay, you're going to the wrong area.
Kenny, Chet, Curtis, Mike, Bix, and Gator
are over here.
We should be over here at the Bluth area
with Gob and Buster and, uh...
uh...
Your brother, uh...
-Michael?
-Michael. Yes.
Sorry. I was thinking of Mike,
the hot seaman.
No, where is Michael?
It doesn't matter. He's not my brother.
This isn't my family.
No, I've spent years...
Yes! Got my "Yes."
I got that big "Yes."
I've spent years trying to fit
into this family, and it's not me.
My life is a fallacy.
♪ Oh, is that a gal I see? ♪
♪ No, it's just a fallacy! ♪
-[man] Yay!
-We loved that. Where's that from?
[narrator] It's from nothing.
But it made her realize this, too.
I don't know
if there's a right time to say this,
but this marriage of ours,
it hasn't been working.
Yeah, there's nothing keeping us together.
It's time to give up our dreams
if they're not working.
You know, your acting career,
this marriage that everyone thinks
is a sham because you're gay.
I'm sorry.
Everyone thinks I'm gay?
Well, I mean, it's kind of a running joke
in the family.
I mean, you know that, right?
'Cause of the misleading way
you talk sometimes.
You're saying the way I talk
makes me sound gay?
When in the last year
have I said anything remotely miss...
♪ It's just a fallacy ♪
-...leading.
-We're chasing things that aren't real.
And maybe we need to go out there
and find out what we're meant to do.
I believe we're thinking the same thing.
-Yeah, we should end it.
-Let's give it another shot.
To the head.  Kill it. Yes.
[narrator] Tobias sat
with his wife's family, feeling lost.
["The Sound of Silence" plays]
Well, you look like I feel.
[narrator] And very misunderstood.
Gay?
No, I...
No.
Who--?
♪ Hello darkness, my old friend ♪
[narrator] Now the story of what happened
when the one man
who was holding his family together
finally let go,
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
Lindsay was looking for inspiration
in finding a new path.
And it only took until the "pray" section
of Eat Pray Love for her to find it.
Soon, she was beginning a journey
to reinvent herself.
[scoffs] I'm doing it again.
I have to let go of these material things.
[narrator] To leave the trappings
of her old life
and try to live with less.
[sighs]
Her immersion into Indian culture
began even before reaching the airport.
And so this daily prayer,
it connects one to the whole.
Yes, the whole of humanity. Yes.
-Look at this guy, ah?
-[tires squeel]
-Stay in your lane, anus tart!
-[honking]
-[Bleep] anus tart!
-God.
[narrator] And after an hour or so
with SkyMall,
where she was proud of herself
for only buying two things,
a self-cleaning litter box
in case she ever got a cat,
and an inflatable hat box
in case she ever got a hat,
she got to a great article
in the in-flight magazine
and found herself filling up
with inner peace and acceptance.
I mean, not right away.
What is she doing back there?
[man groans]
[narrator] Unfortunately, her journey
to let go of her baggage
got off to a bad start at baggage claim,
when she picked up
someone else's baggage...
while hers was picked up
by this man.
Yes, Tobias was confused
about his identity as well,
which is why he couldn't resist a book
the universe had somehow
placed in his path.
They're still reading it, but, well,
I guess I can leave them some love.
[narrator] So he just took
"Eat" and "Pray."
"Eat" was easy, although it provided
no cosmic answers for him.
But it was the part about India
that really got to him.
And so, like the heroine of Eat, Pray...
Tobias decided to get as far away
from his wife as possible.
Coincidence.
[Tobias and narator] And so Tobias
found himself booking passage...
To India.
[narrator] And soon,
he discovered his wife
was also preparing to go somewhere...
I think you have my suitcase?
[narrator] ...far away.
I'm so sorry, Tobias.
Look, I've already packed.
Can I just use this one?
Oh, what the heck!
I guess having matching luggage
isn't so romantic anymore.
And these romantic gestures are possibly
why people think I'm a homosexual.
Well, it's time to correct
old misconceptions.
And that is why I'm making a new start.
A new start.
Filled with compassion and love.
I like that.
Well, I've already got the license plate,
so go cry in your pie!
[narrator] And so Tobias,
hoping to straighten out his image,
set out on a new start.
Beginning with a trip to the airport
in an outfit he pretty much
put together himself.
I guess this is why you never see them
driving convertibles.
[narrator] I'll have to check on that one.
-But it certainly wasn't embraced...
-Look at this guy, ah?
-Stay in your lane, anus tart!
-[Bleep] anus tart!
...by the local Indian community.
You know, you sense
the oneness in all.
And they have normal toilets, right?
[narrator] And his quest
hit a bump early on,
as he struggled to learn the customs
and gestures of the culture
he hoped to adopt.
Oh, God damn it! Am I the only one
who still dresses to fly?
Well, there we go. India clean.
Now, how did I...
[narrator] Unfortunately,
recreating the look
of the traditional Indian garb...
-Are you finished? Oh!
-...turned out to be more difficult...
I look like one of those
hot guys from Spartacus.
...without the aid of Pradeep,
the helpful Indian salesman...
I feel like there was less up top.
...who helped him learn how to tie...
-Ah, I've got it. Okay, that's--
-[garment tears]
Yes, I actually like this better.
[narrator] But he figured he'd wait a beat
on finding his true calling
and watch something
to take his mind off Lindsay...
How could they not have Failure to Launch?
It's an airplane.
What is she doing back there?
[narrator] And after taking the wrong bag
at the airport,
Tobias finally arrived in India...
And so Tobias Funke embarked on a...
Oh, dear Lord, it's...
[narrator]
...where he was very uncomfortable.
...hot! Oh!
[narrator] Not only because the wind
whipped up his mini sarong...
I'm Never Nude!
Oh!
...but because he looked
the wrong direction
when stepping into the street.
Oh, my God.
Did-- did we just hit something?
Shouldn't we stop?
No. It wasn't a cow.
It was just a tourist.
[laughter]
[narrator laughs]
[narrator] And this was how Lindsay's path
to living with less...
This isn't my--
How am I supposed to find out
who I really am dressed like this chick?
[narrator] ...took a brief detour
into a shopping spree
-...at India's famous Mall Mountain.
-It's cute on me.
But I thought
it was supposed to say "Kate."
Oh, no, anything under a small
is considered a David Spade.
I love this jacket.
I'll give you 60 for it.
[narrator] And the spiritual experience
would have to wait
until she got back to the hotel.
Best coat on the mountain.
[narrator] While Tobias' journey
saw nothing more
than the inside of a hospital room,
where the staff was being trained
by the same doctor he'd had in America.
This man here broke his skull
in two places.
Once outside the airport
and once in the elevator
when his sheet got caught
and he was pulled off his gurney.
-[narrator] Literally.
-[laughter]
My name is Tobias...
-Oh!
-[thuds]
Now I've broken my skull in a third place.
On this elephant-guy statue.
-[narrator] That's when the universe...
-[laughter]
You should be a comedy actor.
...gave Tobias a really sweet compliment.
This is the sign that I've been...
[retching]
...looking for.
-But Lindsay's search would continue...
-Hi, uh...
Were you able to book my 3:00 shaman?
...until she could answer
some hard questions.
Oh, yes. Did you want the deep wisdom
or just a light ego cleanse?
We do those by the pool.
There's a pool?
It's hard to tell
because there are so many people in it,
but yes, it is a pool.
Oh, yeah. And, uh...
do you think you can get someone to remove
the smell of lamb from my room?
Of course.
And which animal smell would you prefer?
Which do you prefer?
[narrator] And soon, she got a deeper
treatment than she had hoped for.
You are living a life without love.
How do I learn to be happy?
You know, to love?
When love is near,
your heart will be happy.
You must live life truthfully.
Yeah, no, I do live truthfully,
but I'm just so full of passion.
You are so full of [bleep].
Yeah, yeah.
Although, in my culture,
"full of [bleep]" is kind of like a dig.
You'd never say it to a customer.
But yeah, no, I know what you mean.
This bag is as fake as you are.
Oh. Well, how do I learn?
Just look at the spelling.
-No, I--
-Pull your head out of the sand.
Love is where you left it.
You mean... back home?
The only person back home is Tobias.
You have no children?
[narrator] Lindsay thought
she was being hit on.
No. Why do you ask?
Wait a minute. You're saying
I've come halfway around the world
to find out I need to go back home?
I haven't even gone to the beach yet.
[narrator] She had, it was just
too crowded to see the water.
Excuse me, I'd like to talk to you
about my shaman appointment.
Specifically, what is your policy
on damaged--
I'm sorry. Your AmEx was declined.
Your account is maxed out.
We had to cancel your shaman appointment.
No, no, I just talked to the shaman,
just right back at...
Get out! Get out! Go away!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
I'm sorry to yell at you,
but as I said, it was declined.
So get out.
[narrator] But fortunately,
the universe offered a solution
to her financial problem
that only required
she go back on everything
she'd given up to find herself.
[Lucille] Oh, I've got money
for you, sweetie,
but it means my loving daughter
smiling next to her husband
sitting behind me at the trial.
Would you take a grimace?
[narrator] So it was
with this dual intention
that she reached out
to a husband she'd left behind,
with a new sense of inner peace.
Oh!
Although he wouldn't be able
to reach the phone for hours...
-[Tobias] Leave a message! [beep]
-I'm ready to make this work.
...due to his already weakened spine.
Lindsay shared the news of her epiphany
at a family gathering
when they returned
from their spiritual journey.
To get her hands
on the stimulus money, too, right?
Stop with the prayer hands.
It just looks like you're out of ideas.
Says the least spiritual man I know.
What deal did you strike with her?
What part of her soul did you buy?
All I've asked is that she testify
that I was a wonderful mother
who did her best.
So all of it.
No, Michael. I'm not a whore.
I don't get any of the money
until after I do the disgusting thing.
But I'm not here just for the stimmy.
I'm here because a shaman told me
that love is where I left it.
Which, after much soul searching,
and by process of elimination,
is Tobias.
I got the part.
You know, it's funny,
for I, too, find that I am on a journey.
Although, as we discovered
when our MasterCard bill came back,
it was the same one she took,
but mine has confirmed
that I should redouble my efforts
to achieve the unachievable dream
of being an actor.
A journey that has left me eager
to connect with my true love.
Particularly if she finds her way clear
to covering a 2,000-rupee
City of Hopelessness hospital debt.
The trick is going to be
getting anyone to believe
that her husband is straight enough
to have a true love that's a woman.
What are you implying?
Oh, I don't think there was any implying
going on at all.
Didn't hear any implying.
-I wasn't implying.
-I'm sorry, Mother.
It's just, I've got a bit of a stick
up my bunghole
about what I've now found
is a running joke about me.
But let's be honest.
For 2,000 rupees,
we'd both go down on Matthew McConaughey.
Yes, Michael?
[narrator] Two thousand rupees was $36.
I wouldn't.
So Lindsay and Tobias were making
a new start as a family...
I'm done with this family...
...and Michael was making
a new start without one.
...you're gonna need every dime now.
What's this?
[narrator] But this time,
under his own company name.
Maybe I can give you a tip. Might want
to put a road up to this place.
[Michael] We paved the neighborhood.
Just waiting for the city
to build a road to it.
[narrator] As Michael prepared to sell,
the Funkes prepared to buy,
even though they'd have no money
until after the testimony.
Ready to make a move?
As you can see,
I'm ready for a lot that's new.
Oh! Good heavens!
Right! Well, this is a great area.
There's some wonderful
surgi-centers nearby.
We're doing it. We're really doing this.
[James] Yes! We're gonna
get you in the right house.
And it's just the two of you?
You have no children?
We don't.
We should be honest here.
We have no income flow.
No incoming income flow.
We have plenty of outgoing income.
No savings, no credit.
I mean, we had some stimmy,
but that went to his hospital bills.
-But there's one thing we do have...
-Work ethic!
Right. No work ethic.
But there's one thing we do have,
we do have a daughter.
I was just on auto-pilot before
when I said we didn't.
I should have caught that, yeah, but...
I could've spoken up, but I just wanted
to see if you guys got there.
Well, you guys seem like a great family.
We have to be realistic.
I'm in the real estate business.
It's 2006.
That's all good enough for me.
We're gonna put you in a NINJA loan.
"No income, no jobs, no assets."
And you don't have to pay a penny
for two years.
Oh, NINJA, please!
So we'll take something cozy and intimate.
-A one-bedroom.
-Or bigger.
How about something nice?
A three-bedroom?
-Three does sound bigger.
-Oh, it definitely is.
[narrator] You have to remember
that this was a time
when banks were eager
to create as much debt as possible.
The five-bedroom, four-car garage.
And I know that you guys are gonna be
okay with just one master bathroom,
because a lot of people do prefer two.
You know, they like to just have it.
Maybe separate, so we have it.
-So we have it. That way we have it.
-That way you have it.
Do you think we really need one?
I'm just gonna interrupt for a second.
You don't need a wine cellar
if you want to do wine tastings
in your butler's kitchen.
I mean,
this really isn't what we discussed.
Well, we didn't discuss
any of this, but yes,
-I guess, that way, we have it.
-Well, yeah...
That way, you'll definitely have it.
And then once you have it,
that way you'll have it.
But do we need a gatehouse?
I just put John Beard
into a house with a double gatehouse.
Now, that's John Beard,
he's on television.
No one's gonna look down on you
just 'cause you have
less than John Beard.
-Is this crazy?
-I think so.
-We'll take the double gatehouse.
-Is that what you thought?
-That way, we'll have it.
-We have it.
And that way, you have it.
[narrator] There was a lot of this
going on back then.
This way, we have it.
That way, you'll have it!
Good point!
[narrator] And Tobias began pursuing
the life of an actor.
I'm an actor. You're an agent.
You do the math.
I want you to represent me.
In other words, you do the math.
The money, the negotiating.
You know I'm not
that kind of agent, right?
I'm a real estate agent. I'm a predator.
I sell giant houses to very poor people
who can't afford them
with predatory loans.
That's the money stuff I don't understand.
All you need do is tell people
what a terrific actor I am,
'cause I can't do it believably.
What do you say?
Sounds like it shouldn't be too much work.
Huzzah!
[narrator] And soon,
this out-of-work actor
and his enlightened wife
were starting
their life in their new home.
The Funkes were finally
in a family home...
Maeby, you're gonna be late for school.
[narrator] And what they lost
in coziness...
God, they grow up so slowly.
...they made up for in cavernous...
-And the robot's dead again.
-...unfurnished space.
Poor little guy.
Ran out of juice
before he could reach his...
[door closes]
[narrator] But to pay it off,
Lindsay made an effort
to work on her testimony...
"When I was cold, she clothed me,
when I was hungry, I..."
[chuckles]
Go on.
You don't want me
to say this next part, do you?
I think it tells the story.
But am I accidentally being funny,
or am I purposely being funny?
It's not supposed to be funny.
"Suckled at her champagne glass breasts"
isn't a joke?
Buster wrote it.
Recently?
"I miss you, Mommy.
Camp is scary at times.
When I was cold, you clothed me.
When I was hungry..."
Uh... How do I say this?
Suckled at your champagne glass breasts.
Oh, that's good.
It doesn't matter.
I'll be proofing it anyway.
Just read the copy.
You're getting paid for this.
No. You know what?
The money is not important to me.
My shaman said...
Oh, don't give me that mystical nonsense.
You think you're better than I am,
but you're a lot more like me
than you think you are.
Now, let's take it from,
"I hope she gives me
bubble baths forever."
And I want to smell the suds.
Make the jury wet.
[narrator] While Tobias,
at his new agent's suggestion,
even snuck onto studio lots
to hand out headshots to extras
-and other show business insiders.
-Taft-Hartley pending.
And so Tobias and Lindsay,
who had each asked the universe
for a new start,
only to disregard that
and chase the same things
that had made them unhappy
to begin with,
soon found out
the universe wouldn't be ignored.
The collapse
of the California housing market
is taking a personal toll...
-Oh-oh.
-...with cutbacks here at the station.
In addition, I'm leaving the keys
to my 10,000-square-foot home
in Harbor Shallows here on the desk...
Well, it probably
shouldn't affect our area.
He's over by where the fountain is.
Might I say to them,
good luck getting that [bleep]
raccoon smell out of the gatehouse,
because I never could.
But you and I are okay, right?
I mean, this works, right?
Never better.
[narrator] On the next
Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences...
Michael also has a hard time
hearing the news,
mostly because the main internet
information cable had been severed
when the community pool was installed.
And Michael is left in a ghost town
he himself built.
Well, that's not a great sign.
[caws]
This is why you don't confide
in a competitor.
[caws]