[narrator] On the day of Lucille's trial
for her various crimes at sea,
and in the crab restaurant that served
as the maritime court room...
The defense calls to the oyster bar thing
where they sit:
the adopted daughter, Lindsay Bluth.
Lucille was questioning the wisdom
of threatening to withhold payment
for her daughter's testimony.
Have you seen Lindsay Bluth?
It was a threat that affected
Lindsay's husband Tobias as well,
as they had just purchased
a family home...
What's this? Mother's not going to pay?
...they could neither afford...
She said she'd only pay me
if my testimony is believable, but--
Lindsay!
...nor find each other in.
How am I supposed to say something
like, "I love you, Mother,"
and sound believable?
Oh, Jesus...
Jesus C. Penney!
You know, I wish I had the luxury
of not sounding believable,
but that's not an option
for an out-of-work actor, is it?
Or it's why you're out of work!
Well, I beg one's pardon, but I have been
dying to go to that method acting clinic
that I see on my nightly drives,
but you won't let me.
Because you already wasted all that money
on Carl Weathers' Master Acting Class.
Well, I'm sorry,
but I'm such a starving [bleep]
...that I didn't pay attention
to anything he said.
Oh, well then, maybe I should go
to your method acting class
to make my testimony more believable.
That's actually a good idea.
Maybe you could-- Oh.
Yes.
Well, perhaps we should go together.
Yeah, it might be good for us as a couple.
I do hope so.
I really want to make this work.
Me, too.
I really love you, Tobias.
Oh, Lindsay, we have got to get you
to that acting clinic.
That was with me picturing fudge.
Fudge.
Now the story of what happened
when the one man
who was holding his family together
finally let go
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
To bond with her husband
and prepare for her testimony,
Lindsay had decided to attend
an acting class with Tobias.
This is the first time
I've done something like this with you.
I think I always looked down on it.
Lindsay, I think you'll find that some
of what used to seem clueless about me
is actually something I'm quite good at.
This... is where I belong.
If you're new here,
you need to go to the window.
Fill out this form first.
There's some personal questions on it
like how you first got hooked.
That's an easy one.
You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown.
No, Mame.
No, ma'am? You're a Good Ma'am...
You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown.
-Gypsy.
-You come up here
and be as truthful as possible.
They're starting the monologues.
I think this is from Songs for my Father.
What did you say the name
of this acting class was again?
Method One Clinic.
Okay, I'm gonna go get a coffee.
Garden Grove Method One Clinic.
And that's when Tobias became entranced
by what he first thought was
a Carol Channing impersonator...
I made it in that movie,
The Fantastic Four.
...but soon recognized to be an actress
with a brief movie career.
It was fantastic for me.
I got carried away and I'm like,
"This [bleep] is [bleep] up.
And I'm gonna get my [bleep] together
or I'm gonna be [bleep] up, too."
Anyways, now I'm sober and I'm trying...
...super-hard.
[group applauds]
It was a devastating and personal story.
Okay, notes.
First of all,
it seemed you were slurring a bit there.
I just think you'd have so much more fun
punching those words. Get it out there.
"This [bleep] is [bleep] up, sir!"
I'm sorry.
I'm not familiar with the piece, so...
No, that's it.
But I am familiar with your work
in The Fantastic Four, however.
-You've seen that?
-Of course.
Twenty years earlier,
DeBrie Bardeaux had played Sue Storm
in the low-budget version
of The Fantastic Four,
produced by Imagine Entertainment.
I almost never get recognized
as the Invisible Girl.
I can't believe you saw me.
Well, I thought it was "fantastic...
...for" a threadbare production
of Fantastic Four.
Actually, most of the performance
that had so captivated Tobias
was performed by a bare thread.
This is the gayest Starbucks ever!
Did his fishing line break, too?
Well, my acting career is over.
Don't say that. You've got to say,
"Keep the dream alive!"
That's what helps me.
This is what's helping me.
It's really good.
Here is to our acting addiction.
-Yep.
-May we never be cured.
Are you crying?
I'm crying. Oh, it's a nosebleed.
Thank you so much.
Tobias had found a friend.
-You're neat!
-You're neat.
Lindsay had just discovered
that the Garden Grove Method One Clinic
for Acting
was actually the Garden Grove
Methadone Clinic for Methadone.
And she was reflecting on the shaman...
You are living a life without love
because you only care about appearances.
...who had inspired her return
to her husband.
Love is where you left it.
The only person back home is Tobias.
And was wondering if there was any wisdom
in this at all...
It's not free trade
and if it's not free trade, it's [bleep].
...when she noticed a man.
You don't look like a junkie.
You do. What do you weigh?
Like 90 pounds?
That's so funny.
God, thank you, but no.
If I'm addicted to anything, it's alcohol.
I'm Lindsay. And you're...
Biteme.
I don't like giving my name
to any state organizations,
especially after I got kicked off
the voter rolls.
I accidentally signed up
for the wrong political group.
What group was that?
I don't even remember.
Just some guy in a booth on the boardwalk.
He joined al-Qaeda.
I only signed up because
he was giving away a free beard brush.
That says "al-Qaeda" on it.
But maybe he thought it was
the designer of the brush.
I'm Marky Bark.
Of the tree-freer Barks?
Marky was the son of Johnny Bark,
an activist
that Lindsay had once helped save
and then kill a tree.
I remember thinking one day
he was just gonna fall out of a tree
and break his neck.
Whatever happened to him?
He fell out of a tree and broke his neck.
So are you here alone?
No, I'm with her.
Listen, the only time DeBrie can keep
food down is for about 20 minutes
after she comes crashing off
the methadone.
Would you care to join us as we rustle up
some grub to shove down our mouths?
I would like that very much.
It just so happens we're free today.
I'm not due in court
until, like, eight bells.
The two couples headed off for lunch
despite the fact
that the maritime clock has eight bells
at twelve o'clock in the forenoon
which was when Lucille discovered
that Lindsay wasn't the only Bluth
who didn't show up for her trial.
Gob's excuse was equally compelling.
Gob had been involved
in an escape act gone wrong
and wound up in a storage unit in Tustin.
And on the day of the trial,
he awoke in a hospital,
happy to finally see a familiar shape.
You humiliated me.
You made a mockery of my religion
and you ruined our wedding.
Our first fight.
And like all fights, you're
a little right, I'm a little right.
I sold your cave on Craigslist.
So it was all worth it.
She unknowingly sold the cave
to another Bluth
who missed the trial...
Okay, look up "large mud huts,
can fit 20..."
...while purchasing a larger sweat lodge
for the desert sweat 'n' squeeze
he was in the process of building.
Ship it.
But it was Lucille's son Buster
upon whom Lucille most relied
as her star witness,
as it was his testimony
that was to save Lucille's skin
from charges of stealing the Queen Mary.
Homosexuals kidnapped the boat
and took it on a joyride,
then she realized
that her son fell off the boat
and into the water and she went back.
And a fish swam by my ankle.
-That really happened.
-And he'll be wearing his army uniform,
so I can pretend I'm proud of him again.
I can't find my army uniform.
I thought the jury might like it
if I show up as John John Kennedy.
Oh, yeah, that went over great last time.
And it was offensive. Half your testicle
was hanging out of that thing.
Good!
I'm glad they saw it.
It was like a Motherboy ball, right?
Put on your new uniform
with long pants and keep your ball joke
to yourself, Andrew Dice Clay.
But tensions had mounted.
So you could see why I need the testimony
of someone who's not a hot mess.
-You're a hot mess!
And another mother-son spat...
I'm going to the park!
...sent Buster
to the fruit-laden arms...
I'm juicing now.
Would you like to join me?
...of Lucille's best frenemy,
Lucille Two...
I forgot. Your mother wouldn't allow it.
...who knew what buttons to push.
Let's get juiced.
So there were no Bluths at all
to testify on Lucille's behalf.
Any witness?
Please tell me you're working
on a strategy for us.
It's us now.
Well, we have Lucille Austero.
She's the only one who showed.
I don't think that is good for us.
Nonsense. She owns the company now.
She's got as much to lose as I do.
And she's a dear friend.
I'll do it myself, though.
I need this to go well.
And so it was Lucille who did
the questioning of her new star witness,
although she was clearly green
at screening witnesses.
Thank you for coming to be my witness.
You're such a large shareholder...
I've made a pun!
How could I not do it
for my oldest friend?
Now I've gone and done a double.
A double like your pre-surgery chin.
Or your post-breakfast drink.
I wish you'd come to my rehab clinic.
But anything to help
that Keystone Cop family of yours.
Keystone Cops?
Your references are as fresh
as the wallpaper
in the room of that pretend child
you've had all these years.
-But my friend--
-I shouldn't joke.
None of your family showed up,
you poor thing.
This is such a black mark on all of you.
You should know about black marks.
Your pillow must look
like a Rorschach test.
Not that there'd be anyone to see it.
So as I was saying...
But unfortunately,
their 30-year passive-aggressive dance
was losing some of its passive.
As if everybody in this room couldn't tell
how jealous and conniving you are,
my dear Lucille Austero.
What I knew was that you were stealing
for years. We all did.
That's why nobody was surprised
when you stole that boat.
And I knew you couldn't wait to get
your liver-spotted claws into my company.
Says the woman whose liver can be spotted
from outer space.
-No further questions!
-No further answers!
Am I done?
That's got to be our treasure chest.
You think it went well?
I do.
Tobias and Lindsay drove to meet
their new friends for lunch.
They are such a neat couple.
Are they neat? It's so fun to have
another couple to go out with.
He's amazing.
He's so passionate about real issues.
He's a real activist, like me.
And she's a real actress, like me.
She used to be in big movies,
but then, like a lot of actors,
the teeth go.
But she is the perfect age
to be a Hollywood actress.
42.
Is that all?
Oh, I think this is the place.
It's a barter restaurant.
Marky doesn't believe in money.
-Do I like barter?
-No, it means they don't deal with money.
That's why I swiped that methadone tray.
What interesting friends we've made!
I think this is
exactly what our marriage needed.
Buster wasn't feeling so good
as he awoke hours later than he intended.
Well, that was a freebie.
Mother's trial!
Key witness coming through.
I'm a key...
[soldier]
Play that song in the drizzling rain.
[soldiers]
And Lindsay and Tobias joined
their new friends at C.W. Swappigan's,
a chain that had sprung up
after the economic collapse.
We are like a Salvation Army meets
a soup kitchen, meets a gastro pub,
meets a Marxist
or Leninist type social structure.
These are things that you can order
and these are things that we will accept.
As you see on the bottom,
we don't have the fish
and we're not taking any more lava lamps.
I can see this one's got
that deer-in-the-headlights look.
Oh, no, he just took some methadone.
He thought he was driving
with a cocktail tray.
Speaking of that, how about
mozzarella sticks for the table?
Cocktail tray, light scratching,
for mozzarella sticks!
Six, no sauce.
And maybe some sparkling water
for the table.
I'm sorry, sir.
We're no longer taking hotel soaps.
This is fun.
It's just so refreshing to meet people
with real passion about changing
the status quo.
Lindsay and I don't have a single friend.
Is the food here yet?
I'm not hungry, but...
[man] No cheese!
-Look, it's butter!
-DeBrie...
That's our butter.
We were gonna swap it for dessert.
But Tobias interpreted this
as method one acting.
No, she's improvising.
Yes, ma'am. You seem to be liking
that butter substitute at Swappigan's.
Yes, and what else could you swap for?
Yes, and...
Oh, God.
Oh, I'm out. She's too good.
I don't know who my guy is.
I don't have a guy.
No, she just likes butter.
Let's get you cleaned up.
Marky, I'll take her.
You two just got here.
Have a chat about. I'll clean her up.
-I'm sorry.
-Don't be.
I love it here.
My mother would hate this place.
Lindsay, I have to tell you,
when I first met you,
I thought you were one
of those typical, uptight,
snobby, Newport Beach, vapid
[shouts] nut-busters!
One of those monsters that lives
in a 10,000 square-foot house
that they destroyed the wetlands for.
Those were wetlands?
That explains our Thanksgiving miracle.
What do you mean, you didn't make dinner?
I didn't realize it was Thursday.
There's got to be something here.
Get it!
Chase it into the oven!
Here, little ducky.
-That's a good duck.
-Good duck.
In you go.
This is going to be
the greatest Thanksgiving ever.
I actually do live in a fairly large house
right now.
But we've never made a payment on it.
So you're sticking it to big banking?
Yes.
In fact, I'm only in America
because a shaman told me
that love would come to me when I accepted
who I am and didn't run away.
Sounds like a good shaman.
He was the house shaman
at The Four Seasons, Mumbai,
so you figure he's got to be pretty good.
And he turned into an ostrich at the end.
They're not gonna have that
at the Embassy Suites.
That's funny.
I actually run an ostrich farm.
[woman] ♪ Coincidence... ♪
That's not a coincidence.
♪ Yes, it is ♪
Marky, I've got to tell you,
talking about these social issues,
it's the first time I've felt like myself
in a really long time.
That's because I say what I mean,
I do what I feel. No lies.
Lindsay felt guilty
because she had lied to her mother
in her promise to testify at a trial
she now knew she'd miss.
That's why my motto is,
"Live truthfully and skate through life."
Marky felt guilty
because truthfully, it wasn't his motto.
It was the motto
of a surf and skateboard company.
Live truthfully. Skate through life.
That's amazing.
I haven't felt this deep a connection
with someone in a long, long time.
Other than DeBrie.
I can't believe we just did that.
I can't believe how little give
your teeth have.
So where do you keep your ostriches?
And that's when Lindsay ran off
for a try at a new life.
And Lucille waited after being tried
for her old one.
-Have you heard anything?
-Well, our cashier's pregnant.
And she's not married.
I mean about me.
Oh, you're guilty. Three to five.
Lindsay ran off to a life
she felt was her destiny
and the new lovers discovered each other,
the beautiful female body,
the horrible male.
Wow, that was so... fast.
Thanks, but I didn't know how long
we'd be stuck in traffic, so...
And it sounds like it's moving.
Move it!
-Come on! Let's go!
-Careful!
And as they drove, they learned
so much about each other.
I was always just in such a rush
to grow up and change this world.
Foolishly, the teeth I pulled
were my adult teeth.
I mean, they're just chewing tools.
I don't care about looks.
But you find me pretty though, right?
No. I have no idea what you look like.
I have this condition
called face blindness.
I mean, I can tell you're a woman.
Oh, stop!
But honestly, no,
all I see is, like, eyes and nose,
you know, hair, ears and...
You know, my shaman told me
I should stop caring about appearances.
You know, my whole life,
that's all anyone has ever praised,
all my mom ever cared about.
Because I'm really pretty.
I just thought I'd tell you that
so the story made sense.
I don't care.
But I guess it's kind of karma
that I ended up with someone
who wanted to make love to me
no matter what I look like.
I also wanted to make sure
you weren't a dude.
I can tell with voices usually,
but some guys, they'll fool you
if that's what they want to do.
Hey.
Are you smiling at me?
Buster wasn't smiling either
when he finally made it
to the food courthouse.
-Is it over?
-No, the crab fest just started.
Oh, ma'am, is there a verdict
in the "my mother stole
the Queen Mary" thing?
It's all up on the dailies board.
The fish is frozen here. It's frozen!
Do you really want to spend $30
on frozen fish?
Buster! Where were you?
This is all your fault!
-I was making a bed, two beds--
-Save it!
I can smell the cran-apple on you
from here.
When are you coming home?
I'm serving three to five.
I hope your juicy blender-bender
was worth it.
Don't come to visit me
because I won't see you.
And good luck with your night terrors.
Now no one will be there
to hear your screams!
Won't miss it!
Where do I go?
What do I do? Where do I go?
Where did you get that pirate hat?
And as Buster contemplated a new start,
Lindsay let her husband know
that their new start had reached
a newer end.
I left. I guess you noticed.
But I'm sorry.
I really do care about you, Tobias.
But we were trying to save something
that just couldn't be saved.
And I have to follow my shaman's advice.
I have to be true to myself for once.
And Marky,
he sees me for who I really am.
-He respects me--
-Come on, lady!
You want to wrap this up?
My lady needs to call her loser ex.
Marky, it's me. It's Lindsay.
Oh! Thought you were taking a dump?
I must have scared the [bleep]
out of that lady in the bathroom
when I threw the door open
and told her I loved her.
He loves me?
Sorry. I don't love you.
On the next Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences...
The new lovers arrive and discover
the joys of their new home.
Now that time...
...was also very quick.
Buster returns to the penthouse
and can't bear to re-live the time
he was there
without Lucille before.
I can't go through another two days
like that.
And he decides to pursue a re-trial
of his own.
Buster!
My mother's gone away and I thought
you've always been like a...
-Girlfriend.
-Not what I was gonna say!
And Lindsay,
free of her ex and her own mother,
awakens to a destiny foretold to her
in India...
Get away from her! Don't mess with her!
She's none of your business!
-Thank you.
-I said get away from her, you slut!
You're scaring the bird!
...only to find out she had a new mother.
She lives with us now.
And Mom...
She tells me she's pretty.
I have the worst [bleep] shaman.