[upbeat guitar intro plays]
[playing rock music]
[narrator]
Senior year in college is the time
when students start to decide
upon a career path.
-And how could rock and roll music...
-[song ends]
And... that's where the song
should have ended.
-[narrator] ...not be George Michael's?
-So...
I guess we all got a little carried away.
You sure? We all ended at the same time.
That's because you all sped up together.
[chuckles]
If I was playing in your band,
I would say,
"Hey, let's do the whole
fast and loose with tempo thing."
But this is about my demo tape
to Juilliard.
And they've gotta dig what I do so much
that they start an entire department
for woodblock.
So, I'm sorry guys,
and you're leaving. Okay.
They left early. Proves my point.
-[door shuts]
-She was cute.
They were playing
way too loud anyway, right?
-Could you even hear the woodblock?
-Right at the end.
We could record you separately
and then mix it louder on the computer.
Then I'm not playing in a band.
I mean, the whole point of the band
is to showcase my amazing internal clock.
That's something you have to be born with.
[narrator] Or bred with,
which was the case with George Michael,
who, as a small child,
appeared in a promotional video
-for a developmental tool called BabyTock.
-BabyTock will give your child
a head start in math.
And, if I were a doctor,
I would guarantee you that it would also
boost their brain power by 110%.
That's a lot of brain power.
You've been using BabyTock, correct?
For how long?
Two months. But George Michael really
enjoys listening to the sound.
And would you say it's...
changed the power of his brain?
-Uh, well, that's impossible--
-[woman 2] ...to deny!
I've always wanted a smart baby.
This thing really works, George.
[narrator] In fact,
it came from something that didn't...
So we're stuck with five thousand
of these worthless cornballers?
[narrator]
...when they were looking to recoup
some of their costs
after an ill-fated foray
into the fry-at-home snack food market.
[crowd gasps]
Whoa, whoa. They're not worthless.
You know? The timer still works.
No numbers on it, but it's very loud.
[loud ticking]
Perfect, for those who like
the sound of a clock
-but don't know their numbers.
-That's good.
We'll sell this to babies-- [shouts]
Mother of-- [bleep]
[sighs] We should put these in cribs.
That's not a half puny thought.
[narrator] But for now, George Michael
would be keeping
the Juilliard thing confidential.
...stays confidential from my dad.
He's never gonna want me to pursue
a career in--
-Hitting a block of wood.
-In music. Yes.
He still thinks of me
as the same George Michael that I was
before my life blew apart.
[narrator] He was referring to this...
Before the world cracked me open
and I became the guy
that you're looking at now.
George Michael 2.0.
God, I hate my name.
[narrator]
Ironically, George Michael's Uncle Gob
was at that very moment
living the dream of a young,
successful musician.
He felt as if he were in the center
of an entourage,
even though he was three away
from the center at the closest,
and was 20 years older
than the young musician Mark Cherry,
whose dream it actually was.
Still, Gob's life had become
a blur of parties...
-[all shouting]
-...and shame.
But Gob had a trick for helping him
forget the shame.
Unfortunately, it also helped him forget
that he tried to forget the shame.
[sighs] Hey!
-Remember me?
-And soon, Gob found himself
experiencing what, on the street,
is referred to...
-as a "roofie circle..."
-I won't forget this!
...whereby a roofie is taken
the day after a degrading event...
too late to erase the memory
of the degrading event itself...
but not too late to erase the prior day's
attempt to erase the event.
[whistling indistinctly] Hey! Remember me?
Thus, with no memory
of taking the roofie...
Do you still sell these?
...but the memory of the event
very much alive...
Oh, I should grab a, uh... Oh.
...the victim of the roofie circle
finds himself constantly trying
-to re-erase the memory...
-What's with the scary guy?
-[man starts to respond]
-Cállate.
...but only succeeds in erasing the memory
of the attempt to erase the memory.
Days turn into weeks,
weeks turn into months...
-What's up with the Christmas decorations?
-Es tiempo.
...as relationships grow testier.
And that's how Gob,
-instead of facing a little shame...
-Hey, remember me?
-¡No! ¡No más!
-...ended up in a Mexican hospital...
-Do you remember me?!
-...with stage four syphilis.
[groaning]
Now, the story of what happened
when the one man
who was holding his family together
finally let go,
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
[narrator] George Michael was frustrated
by the limitations of his musical gift.
[George Michael] Maybe using a band
to showcase my woodblock skill
is a dumb idea.
I'm never gonna be louder
than an electric guitar.
[P-Hound] Too bad there's no such thing
as an electric woodblock.
[George Michael]
Sounds like a mother of an invention.
[narrator] And so they set to work
inventing a downloadable app
-that would be just that.
-You'll always have a woodblock with you.
I can't believe nobody's ever done this.
[narrator] A quick something search
would have shown the guys
that there were already
three woodblock apps on the market.
So, there are three on the market.
...which they did.
[in Spanish] We are in the jungle.
But they were undeterred.
Download them. Come on, let's do it.
I hope we're not doing this
on my account.
No, we're doing it so we can see
what the competition is like.
No, I mean on my iTunes account.
-It's 99 cents.
-Times three.
[woodblock thud effects]
[narrator] But they did,
and soon they realized
what kind of competition
they were up against.
-These are a [bleep] joke.
-[laughing] I know!
Where are the mallet options? There's
no choice of wood weight or grain type.
There's no diameter hole option.
What is this? BabyTock?
-BabyTock?
-You know, the sharp metal box
that you put in a crib--
Is that not a well-known...?
In fact, it had only been used
on one other child,
and its claims of creating math prowess
were undermined by her own performance
in the field...
-Gonna need special tutoring.
-...but also by the fact
she was currently in her fourth
senior year of high school.
But having lost her show business job...
You're fired.
...Maeby would have to live off
her royalty checks until she graduated,
which is why she was soon forced
to sneak into the penthouse apartment
without her mother knowing.
Although, it's worth noting
that her mother
had also previously snuck
into the penthouse apartment
without her mother knowing.
-And as Maeby checked out the mail...
-Oh, my God!
...her mother's ostrich was in heat
and eager to check out the female.
And the ostrich eventually found
what she thought was another ostrich.
Tobias, however, would shortly
be sneaking into the same penthouse
that his daughter, Maeby,
had moments earlier snuck out of.
The dream of a successful acting career
that Tobias shared with his
girlfriend DeBrie wasn't panning out.
Something was forced to admit
when the depths of DeBrie's
desperation for money...
We're broke.
...became almost clear to him.
You can't sell
your Fantastic Four costume.
-[ostrich squealing]
-[grunting] Somebody help!
-Lucille Two!
-And soon, the reward would be given
-to Lucille Two's hero.
-There's my hero!
You know the doctor said if that bird
had gotten through
my second layer of makeup,
it could have done permanent damage
to my skin.
And I want to repay you.
You're a doctor. And you're out of work.
-Well--
-How would you like to work for me?
At Austerity.
The rehab center? That's yours?
My brother Argyle runs it day to day,
but we are so understaffed.
You'd be such a gift.
It would only pay 120 grand a year
to start.
What do you say?
Tobias, whose girlfriend had nearly
sold her body in front of him...
knew that everyone at some time
has to give up an old dream.
Eh... Mm... Eh...
-But this wasn't the time.
-No.
Gob had a dream, too.
Of partying and picking up girls.
See, I told you I knew him.
Can I get a picture with him
to show my five-year-old?
-You have a five-year-old?
-[narrator] But it was old too.
Granddaughter.
Oh, yeah.
Or at least, it had become old...
-Run. Run!
-...to the man who'd made it possible.
[bleep] Getaway.
But George Michael's music dream
was in full flower...
Woodblock.
-[man] Unavailable.
-It's taken.
[narrator] ...as he finished an app
he decided to call...
-Blockwood.
-[man] Also unavailable.
-It's taken.
-BlockBlock.
No. People are gonna think we're
in the chicken noise business.
-How is that a chicken noise?
-You know.
Look, it's kind of hard to do
in these matador pants, but you know...
Block--
[man] FakeBlock is available.
Would you like to take it?
Okay. They have FakeBlock.
Okay, yes, we'll take that.
-That will be $5000.
-That's no problem.
Could you hang on to that for me, please,
and I'll call you back. Thank you.
It's $5,000 for the domain name,
and then there's this whole
XML website fee.
I got the last one.
That was 99 cents.
Times three!
[narrator] That's what led George Michael
to the Student Employment Office.
We actually have a variety of subjects
that high school students
need tutoring in.
Take a look at that list and let me know
if there's anything
that you've handled before.
[narrator] There was.
Although George Michael couldn't imagine
it was the same Maeby.
Is this F in "Maeby F" her last name
or her grade?
It's her last name.
But her most recent grade is...
Well, this just shows
an Elvis Presley head.
So, that bad?
I'll take her.
Stay on top of her.
You need to ride her pretty hard.
Don't be afraid to crack the whip.
-Hey, you must be--
-[narrator] George Michael's new dream
had been replaced with an old one.
-This is the girl you broke up with?
-Huh? What is this?
I can't wear this.
Well, we dated for a while,
but, you know, I was a kid,
and I didn't know how to kiss yet.
I don't know, for whatever reason,
I listened to my dad,
who said we shouldn't make it work.
-Was she your first?
-Cousin? No.
Why would your mind go right to-- No.
It's just, he was right. We were kids.
I wasn't yet O.S.
-"Overtly Sexual."
-Right.
As I live and breathe.
Crazy. That's just crazy.
-[knocking at door]
-Okay, so listen...
after I let her in, you go
and try and keep my dad out. All right?
I can't let him get in the way
of this one.
Hey, you must be--
[narrator]
But first, he had to cover his tracks.
-What?
-This had to look like fate.
-George Michael?
-Huh? What is this?
-[Maeby laughing]
-What are you... doing here?
As I live and breathe...
But for the phrase,
"As I live and breathe," he nailed it.
-I'm supposed to tutor a kid from--
-High school. Yeah.
-That's me.
-Crazy.
That is just crazy.
[narrator] And despite his deceit,
he couldn't help but challenge
her strategy for staying in high school.
You have to make a living, right?
Don't you need an education?
-Don't forget, I'm a Harris.
-Harris?
Yeah, someone who "in-harris"
a lot of money.
Oh, an "heiress." Yeah, well...
I wouldn't put all my ands in that basket.
You know, it's fine. You don't get it.
You've never been a risk-taker.
I like to [bleep] with people.
That's what I do.
-I'm making a statement.
-[P-Hound] I love it.
I knew you were cool
when I saw you wearing that shirt.
[narrator] It seemed George Michael
wasn't the only deceitful one
in the double castle.
I get it too.
I love it too.
George Michael found himself
less overtly sexual than he'd hoped.
I made a 40-year-old woman cry in Spain.
I love making love to Spanish women.
Get out.
And with his roommate gone,
George Michael slipped back
into seduction mode.
So... a man, a woman.
Let's solve for "X."
I don't know you're talking about.
In algebra, you have an unknown element,
and we call it "X,"
and then you have to solve for it
to find out what number X is.
"X" isn't a number.
You don't even really know... the basic...
[narrator] But in that moment, the urge
to educate her was more powerful
-than the urge to kiss her.
-Let me show you real quick.
So if you take something like this:
"3x+1 = 10"...
[narrator]
And with the algebra lesson complete,
George Michael pivoted back
to his overtly sexual seduction.
When I say, "You and me and a bedroom,
let's solve for 'X,'" um...
I'm stating it as a kind of formula.
Yeah, let's get wasted.
Let's drink that formula.
It's not that kind of formula.
I'll show you what a formula is
real quick, 'cause that's very important.
-Gonna wanna...
-[knocking]
-But when the door opened...
-Dad!
...George Michael's
window of opportunity closed.
-P-Hound is yanking our chain again.
-Uncle Michael!
-[Michael] Oh, my God!
-And after a brief reunion,
-George Michael had another opportunity...
-Told her about your software?
-...to impress his cousin.
-No.
He's got this privacy software.
Keeps people from stealing your stuff.
Tell her, pal.
So, it's privacy software
that's also anti-piracy?
George Michael weighed his options.
Maeby had chastised him
for not taking risks,
and what would be a bigger risk
than perpetuating a lie about software
just to ignite the passions of a woman?
Of course it would be a lie,
and since Maeby wouldn't know
it was a lie,
he wouldn't appear to be taking a risk.
Perhaps the bigger risk
was to tell his father he was lying.
That he came up with it
because he wanted his father to leave
so he could enjoy what remained
of his senior year.
After all, he wondered, wouldn't that be
the course of action taken
by an overtly sexual man?
A man who owns a pair of matador pants?
He had not responded now for 41 seconds,
according to his unfailing internal clock,
and it was time to come clean.
Well, thanks. Yeah.
It's just a Boolean-driven aggregation
of what programmers call "hacker traps."
[narrator] And he found himself suddenly
and effortlessly
tapping into a long inbred instinct
for lying.
A Bluth taking his first steps in deceit.
And she seemed to be impressed.
But to close the deal,
he couldn't lie to himself any longer.
There was someone he needed to get away.
It's called FakeBlock.
His father.
Mark Cherry also had someone
he needed to get away.
♪ Stay away, get away ♪
-♪ Get away ♪
-He'd even written a song about it.
Yeah, just like that.
But the lyrics were too subtle
for Gob to notice.
It's worth noting that Maeby
wasn't impressed
with the software George Michael
had lied about.
Can I get a Crown 12 neat,
water back.
She was depressed.
I gotta start bringing some cash in,
you know?
Everyone's just passing me by.
George Michael, Kitty Sanchez...
Drinks for the house.
This guy?
These guys are making a fortune
off that To Entrap a Local Predator show
they're on.
[narrator]
And although she did briefly pursue
-a job in show business...
-You looking for a new bait house?
...she soon felt worse when she saw
her supposedly 17-year-old boyfriend...
Isn't this guy a little too young
to be in here?
No, he's with us.
...had a better one.
-[cop] You fitting in at the high school?
-He's a cop.
They accepting you?
[narrator]
But George Michael ended up...
It's a fake profile that leads hackers
away from your actual data.
-...with a great idea for software.
-I mean, think about it.
Everyone has something that
they want removed from the internet.
George Michael certainly did.
-[dramatic instrumental music plays]
-[girls laughing]
[speaking Spanish]
Oh, my God.
If we could make something like that,
it could be bigger than Facebook.
Who wouldn't want something like that?
Think you can do it?
-No.
-No, of course not.
No. I mean--
This is my chance with Maeby,
and I can't even get rid of my own father.
What if we just did a vote?
Just the roommates.
We do a quick vote,
and it's, "Ciao, father-o."
He's gonna know who voted against him.
-Not if I get him to vote against himself.
-[chair squeaking, cracking]
Why would he do that?
He wouldn't. I was just leaning back
so it looked like I--
I got this chair again, didn't I?
Maybe I just need to be clear, and say,
"I'm putting up a wall.
We need to rework our whole system here."
Sounds like you guys are working
on your privacy software, huh?
-Hey! How'd you find me?
-[narrator] And long story short,
Michael did end up thinking
the voting out a roommate idea
was his own.
And it's, "Adios, broth-iero."
It cannot fail.
[somber piano music plays, stops]
-That was fun.
-Did he look betrayed to you?
He kind of always looks that way.
[narrator]
Gob was about to be betrayed as well,
for that night, Mark Cherry and his entourage
were quickly going out for the evening.
Hurry, before he sees us. Come on.
-Hey, guys, where we going?
-But, not quickly enough.
I'll drive, I just gotta
put my my sick bees in the trunk.
Whoa! I can't be near bees.
I wrote a whole [bleep] song about it.
[narrator] It seems that Malibu
wasn't the only colony
that was collapsing on Gob.
You've gotta get your bees out of here.
They're sick.
They're gonna collapse the whole colony.
Did you tell him about the sick bees?
Jesus, I just said that!
You're late to the party again!
What am I supposed to do with sick bees?
You know, I don't really care.
I got problems of my own.
I saw you pointing.
Yeah, you saw that.
But you didn't see the tumor on my neck
six months ago, did you?
Your venemous hatred has killed my bees.
[narrator] Perhaps this was the moment
that Gob could sense the tide was turning.
It's my fault, guys. I made a big mistake.
[narrator] In an effort to prove
he provided a valuable service...
-[bees buzzing]
-...Gob stopped in front of a club
-to pick up some women...
-[Gob] Oh, ladies!
...where, moments earlier,
Tobias shared with DeBrie
that Lucille Two had offered him
-a valuable job.
-You turned it down?
-Mm-hmm.
-I almost [bleep] a guy for a hamburger,
and you turned down 120,000 a year?
To keep our dream alive, yes, I did.
-I thought you'd be proud of me.
-[sobs] You're worse than Marky.
He couldn't see me, but you can't hear me.
[sobbing]
[narrator] The setback sent
an emotionally fragile DeBrie
back to her old ways,
including a night of being passed around
amongst Hollywood creeps.
[Gob] Who wants to party with Mark Cherry?
-Which is how Gob...
-[rock music playing]
...kept his old dream alive, after all.
That's one forget-me-not saved,
huh, fellas?
-Ah, looks like we got a real live one.
-[woman] Whoo-hoo!
By "live," I mean barely alive.
[narrator]
But a dream can also be a trap.
[crickets chirping]
[indistinct police radio chatter]
All right, guys. What have we got?
It's quiet out there.
We, uh, we better be ready.
Yeah. I'm a man.
Don't make it look like makeup.
Car.
Is that guy one of ours?
Look at the license plate.
Looks like we got ourselves an Anus Tart.
[narrator]
Yes, Tobias had hit rock bottom...
Hey. It's Big Daddy.
I thought I'd try to call you
before I surprised you.
Things are...
really looking up,
-and, uh-- Hello?
-[beeps]
Damn it. What Sudden Valley does
to these cell phones.
[narrator] ...and was finally ready
to reconnect with his family.
[man on radio]
Anus Tart is turning on Tracy Lane.
He's peeping up George Michael.
All right, guys,
let's entrap a local predator.
Who, what, when, where, why, and how.
Who, what, where, when, why, and how.
Who, what, when, where?
[man on radio] Anus Tart is approaching...
[narrator] And Tobias' dream of finally
getting to be in a TV show...
-[Tobias sings indistinctly]
-...was finally coming true.
Is there a little girl here
all by herself?
[narrator] And perhaps it was this
that would finally get him to admit
that he sometimes did speak...
Daddy needs to get his rocks off.
[narrator] ...in a misleading way.
On the next Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences...
-Gob's dream becomes a trap too.
-[indistinct chatter]
-Take off your--
-[all] Clothes!
-We're having a good time.
-We're having a great time.
-Hey, Getaway?
-Yeah.
You know what would be really cool?
If you shut the partition.
It'd be like, uh... like a joke.
Like you're our limo driver
and we don't want to talk to you.
That would be hilarious, right?
Yes, very good, sir.
-Very good.
-[music, chatter fading]
Right?
Be like, "Eh, I'm just driving
the Queen of England.
But we're still taking our clothes off."
[narrator]
And excluding Gob allows this to happen.
What's stashed in here?
-[loud buzzing]
-[all screaming]
"A lot of traffic out here today,
Miss Daisy."
[screams continue]
-[sings indistinctly]
-[narrator] On the plus side,
Gob's bees end up feeling good enough
to sting again.
♪ Getaway, getaway ♪
[man]
On the next To Entrap A Local Predator...
Predator gets its first rock solid case.
[high voice] Have some lemonade!
Pretty good lemonade, huh?
It is. Is there alcohol in--
-John Beard.
-Why are you here?
I'm here to see my little girl.
I wanted to show her Daddy's thing.
-Okay.
-So it's your daughter you're here to see.
Yes.
Maeby.
Well, you're free to go. She's not here.
[man] But this creep
won't take "go" for an answer.
That's all right, I'll stay. I'll wait.
And this creep makes himself
right at home.
[John] Give me a minute.
-He's not leaving.
He's not leaving.
Tell him there's a raccoon
in the backyard.
[John] Guess what?
There's a raccoon on the patio.
[scoffs] Bull-- [bleep]
Where is that little guy?
[man] And this guy turns out to be
a real comedian.
[Tobias groaning]
I just broke my skull in a fourth place.
The patio! Oh...
[theme music playing]