[narrator] Three days before
many of the Bluths
would come back together,
Lindsay Bluth was on her way
to the first phase
-of an act of political sabotage...
-My dad's tux looks good on you.
...with her face-blind boyfriend.
I don't care.
Together, they were targeting...
This guy... Herbert Love.
A candidate whose campaign slogan
...say High-low to my Low-high plan.
The "Low" is for low taxes.
[narrator] ...was embraced by everyone
from the very wealthy...
...and who doesn't want high income?
[narrator]
...to their bankers and tax attorneys.
It's worth noting that this
was the same Herbert Love
who'd recently adopted Lindsay's brother..
.Buster Bluth.
We could use a Blind Side monster.
And Herbert was soon
using the veteran at rallies.
Hold your government hand out...
...as a symbol of government waste.
Let's give freedom from government
a big thumbs up.
...although Buster had not mastered
the use of his Army-issued, bionic hand.
Buster's actual father, George Sr.,
needed the help of Herbert Love...
-What?
-He's got a rally tonight.
...to gain support for a wall project...
...to separate the US and Mexico
to keep out the immigrants.
which some considered insensitive.
-Your idea.
-Which was my idea!
George Sr. was feeling
more sensitive by the day.
I'd be lucky to sell a glass of lemonade
for $1,000 today,
But Marky's idea was very different.
Three days before the event,
I'm going to take the explosive
and hide in the podium...
...and he had planned an act
of glittery social protest
You're going to knock on the podium door.
Let me know the coast is clear.
When Love steps up to the podium
at exactly eight o'clock, blam!
Thing is, I can't find
the glitter anywhere...
But Lindsey had only signed on
to the project
because she was mad at her mother,
Lucille.
"From Gangie for Facelift."
Mother.
...over what she assumed her mother
had sent her daughter Maeby:
a check for plastic surgery.
What makes you think I wrote a check
to your daughter?
In fact, it was Maeby's royalty check
for this film.
But when she revealed she was
living in the penthouse...
The apple does not
far from the tree fall.
Lindsay felt she needed to prove...
I am like you nothing.
I am a political activist.
...which is why she decided...
I'm in.
-Let's bomb the bastard.
-Yes!
but as she pulled up to the hotel,
her stridency was waning
Look, um...
I have this check that my mother
wrote for my daughter...
It can buy us a lot of leaflets
against Love.
And also a lot of Nature's Miracle.
You know there's a huge sale
going on at Petco.
No, never. Rip it up. No money.
Don't worry. I've thought of everything.
He had.
Except for someone to watch Cindy.
But she's locked in.
What's the worst that can happen?
As it turned out, she wouldn't be
locked in for long...
...as Maeby would let the ostrich
in heat out
while looking for the very check Marky
had told Lindsay to rip up.
No money.
...before going to squat in a podium
for three days.
What a great day to step out
onto an over-irrigated golf course
and play a game that wastes
vast acres
of usable, farmable land.
And while she didn't find the check
she did find an invitation
to an award show
that honored young Hollywood.
I'm getting an Opie?
The only bigger honor
would be having an award like that
named after you, I guess.
But it was an important morale-booster,
as she was jealous of her
cousin George Michael's accomplishments
-as a college senior.
-Have you told her about your software?
So, it's privacy software
that's also anti-piracy?
Thanks, yeah.
It was neither.
In fact, it was actually this...
...programmers call "hacker traps."
which uses false meta data...
...a fake woodblock app...
But George Michael could see
he was impressing her
so he continued the lie...
It's called Fakeblock.
Plus, he wanted to expose her
to his newly overtly sexual persona.
Just trying to be those guys.
That's how George Michael
came to make his move.
Are you gonna come by
on Thursday?
I don't think so.
I have this thing in L.A.
Can you blow it off?
You might want to get
graduating high school
out of the way.
I'm getting a Lifetime Achievement Award
at this gala.
Might want to get that
out of the way too, I guess.
You want me to go with you to that?
I could pick you up at your place.
They're actually shooting a thing
at my place.
As it turns out,
they'd end up just clubbing a Thing.
Yeah, that might actually be a good idea,
because I can't bring my friends
without permission from their parents.
With the exception
of her boyfriend, Perfecto,
about whom she recently discovered...
He's a cop.
Maeby realized she needed
to get something incriminating
on Perfecto
before he could get her
kicked out of school.
But she was soon to learn.
that her grades might beat him to it.
I got you tacos.
I hope that's okay,
because you're gonna sit here and study.
No, I can't.
Young lady, you better pull it together,
or you're not going to graduate.
Are you on drugs?
Because from what I hear,
there might be an undercover cop
at this school.
How long do you wanna stay in high school?
You're 17.
And that's when she remembered
that Perfecto thought
she was 17 too.
You know what? I think I will do better
once I get a little Mexican in me.
Maeby and Perfecto weren't the only ones
acting younger than they really were.
And in an effort to impress
the young entourage
that was growing weary of his act,
Gob stopped in front of a club
to pick up some women.
And so the night before Mark Cherry
was also due to be honored
at the Opies,
the gang from the Malibu Colony
met the gang from Gob's bee colony.
I'm like, "Those are police boats..."
So everybody's running around...
To the entourage,
the evening was a complete disaster.
Drunken, sick and covered with bee stings,
they had truly hit bottom.
But to the man they called Getaway,
it was an amazing night,
and he couldn't wait to forget it.
Fun day.
Fun night.
Now the story of what happened
when the one man
who was holding his family
together
finally let go,
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice,
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
On the day of the Opies,
Gob headed out to make sure
everything was in order,
trying not to arouse the gang
he felt he'd won back,
with what he dimly recalled
to be a fun night.
Wake up!
And that night, a softening George Sr.
arrived to meet the candidate
Herbert Love at his rally.
So... tender.
At the same hotel that was hosting
Young Hollywood's Opie Awards.
[crowd laughing]
It's really nice to be
out with you as adults.
In Spain they don't even
eat dinner until after 11 p.m.
I'm going to mingle with 13-year-olds
who think they still play fifth grade.
And, as he told himself,
it was okay to unleash
his overtly sexual persona
on his cousin...
Gentlemen, start your engines.
...he inadvertently ogled his aunt,
who'd arrived in disguise.
And Maeby ran into her
old studio boss, Mort Meyers.
I'm actually getting
the Lifetime Achievement Opie tonight.
I'm very sorry.
They only give that award away
to somebody after they die
or, even worse, after your career's dead.
Really?
Consider yourself lucky...
They told you your career was over.
I didn't find out until I was locked out
of my office.
I passed on Hunger Games.
It wasn't the most graceful of exits.
That's the way the cookie crumbles.
This is for you.
Thanks, man.
Actually, the exit was pretty graceful.
I think I just remember it that way
because it got dicey when I was
sneaking back in
to take a [bleep] on Sid's desk.
But do what I do.
When they kick you out of the business,
save face by starting
your own internet company.
You started an internet company?
It's the real deal.
It's a system that automates provision--
And, once again, she found herself
with someone who had not
only moved on with their life,
but done so in ways
she couldn't understand.
...overseas financial transactions.
It's called Schnoodle.
-Schnoodle.
-It was a busy night at the hotel.
Take a hat. We got 18,000 of them.
And as Maeby put on a brave face...
George Sr. put on a braver one.
I just think there'll be lot of support
flowing in this relationship.
And your base...
You got a point behind
all those teeth?
If you support the wall,
I'll give you a piece of the action
-Action?
-Yeah.
-Action Jackson?
-Yes, sir.
Do I look like Carl Weathers to you?
No, no.
Do I look like someone
who eats at CW Swappigan's?
I don't want to be the one to say it,
but I happen to be fond of
redheads and greenbacks.
George Sr, had neither.
How would you like both?
Buenas noches...
I will be needing a room...
-How many nights?
-Two.
No, just one night.
I thought you were saying people.
-And how many beds?
-Two.
No, one bed...
Why give her the option?
Keep itn real simple.
One bed, one night, two people
that's solved for X.
I hate Young Hollywood.
Maeby soon ran into an actress she knew...
from the time before that actress
cleaned up her act.
Next time, don't pocket it.
Pay for it.
♪ I mean come on ♪
And you're getting the Lifetime
Achievement Award?
You want me to play
the bagpipes at your funeral?
You know, I can laugh about it,
because I'm actually on the upswing.
I was just telling Mort here...
that I've actually started
my own internet company.
I was just about to tell you.
-How do we know each other?
-We don't.
That's what it is.
Schnoodle's dead. Fakeblock
is the next big thing.
But George Michael was
surprised to hear Maeby
talking about a software.
...called Fakeblock.
What's this?
You're talking about Fakeblock?
Yes, your privacy software.
...that didn't exist.
-How does your privacy software work?
-It's private.
Can I talk to you for a second, please?
I don't want people to know
I'm doing this.
Everybody has to know about this, okay?
This could be big for me.
I could make Fakeblock huge.
Maeby, there is no company.
Fakeblock is just a software
that I'm developing.
And the whole point is that it's private.
So you can't
be telling people about it.
We've got to tell people about it.
I just got a Lifetime Achievement Award.
I'm finished.
And also, I think you should consider
calling it The Fake Block.
-It's cleaner, like "the Netflix."
-It's just not ready.
There's still a bunch
of programming problems.
You can get it ready, George Michael.
Think they invite animals
and ask 'em to wait
while they build the zoo?
No, that would be a bloodbath.
Yeah, a total [bleep] bloodbath.
-We have no money to start a business.
-Don't worry.
I'll get the ball rolling
with free publicity
when I accept my award.
Come on, this could be my only chance
to be a "hairess."
A "hairess"?
You can still be the boss, okay?
Just don't want people to know
I'm working with my cousin.
So you are not my cousin.
You are not George Michael Bluth.
I'm great with that.
In fact, you know what
might really help us sell it...
Oh, heiress!
You don't pronounce the "h."
-And that's not what heiress means.
-I pronounce the "h."
But that's not how the word--
We say words the way we say them
for a reason...
So, what is this?
Is this another one of these
social networking things?
Because I am so over those.
I tried to deactivate my Facebook profile.
It's easier to get out of Scientology.
Well, this is actually the opposite
of Facebook.
It's the anti-social network.
It prevents piracy. Right?
Really?
Rebel Alley.
George Mi-hairess.
George Maharis.
And that's how George Michael
finally got himself
a new name.
Strong, rugged... untainted.
Yes, George Maharis.
Perfecto.
De nada.
That's my undercover cop boyfriend.
I'm trying to get him in bed.
Boyfriend?
So funny that didn't come up in the car.
George Michael had just discovered
that Maeby had a boyfriend.
So, how does it work?
How does what work?
Your privacy software.
How does it protect you from piracy?
I don't know.
Don't worry about it.
No, you really piqued my interest.
I'm sorry.
But some women don't forget
being told no.
Marion Ross comes to mind.
And Maeby set to work
entrapping this local predator.
I know why you're here.
Promise you won't tell anyone at school.
I'm just a huge fan of teen stars.
Yeah. Very convincing.
You're a better actor
than most of the kids here.
Even Zack and Cody.
Are they here?
I thought they were filming
a movie in Maui.
Look, I may only be 17, Perfecto,
but I know you're a cop.
There's that cop stare.
I got to tell you...
I find it very sexy.
Okay,
I'm a cop.
I'm working here undercover.
We're hunting down an ex-CIA operative
named Estevez,
who's gone rogue--
It's the kids from Modern Family.
He's become a drug kingpin
and his son goes to Newport.
There's something going down tonight
or possibly even at Cinco-- [yells] Rico!
Wow, you are good.
I have to be.
Our lives depend on it.
To be continued.
You better believe it.
Rico!
But George Sr. was far from rico himself,
despite promising Herbert Love
he had money.
But at least he could go home.
with some coconut shrimp.
I should have known you'd be here.
supporting this right-wing,
dangerous crack-pot.
Lindsay, I forgot. You dyed your hair.
What are you doing here?
I'm supporting Love as well.
We're both doing that.
Oh honey, I wanted to contact you
every single day since last May.
I haven't seen you since January.
Yeah, the first four months,
I was in denial.
How are you?
Are you good?
Do you have any money?
Not really.
Except for a $50,000 check
your wife sent to my daughter
for plastic surgery.
What kind of woman does that?
I thought there was no money left.
Oh no.
That's awful.
She's just precious the way she is.
Does Maizie even know?
Her name is Maeby.
You don't think "Maizie" is cuter?
You know what I want to do?
I want to take this...
and I want to deposit it
in a trust fund...
that she can't open until she's 21.
She was 22 at the time.
I guess I can't use it anyway.
Are you kidding me?
You are the most beautiful little girl.
If you have any more work,
your cartilage is going to collapse.
Let me see if I can...
There you go.
And that's when George Sr...
Got the check.
...finally tipped a black man.
Man...
I am going to put this on my wall.
It was then that Lindsay
ran into a daughter,
whose $50,000 check she'd just given away
stealing some coconut shrimp.
Of course you're here.
I should have known you'd be supporting
this right-wing, dangerous crack pot.
No, I am here undercover
with my boyfriend.
We are going to take down Love
with a random act of senseless
non-violence.
Maeby felt a foreign feeling.
I actually respect that.
Thank you, Maeby.
Which is why, for the first time
in her adult life...
So, what are you doing here?
Maeby was totally honest with her mother.
I'm getting a Lifetime Achievement Award
for my work in the entertainment business.
I tried.
Tell your therapist I tried.
I'm not in therapy.
Then I must have done something right.
And soon she was saying
farewell to Hollywood
in a way she hoped they'd remember.
Thank you, Kirk Cameron,
for that incredibly Bible-y introduction.
Okay, tie yourself to your chair,
because this is
going to be a rough [bleep] ride.
I'm leaving this [bleep], dying business,
to join the software game.
Double [bleep] news flash.
I'm starting Fakeblock...
with George Maharis,
the world's first anti-social network.
So you can take this Opie and shove it up
your [bleep],
because I will [bleep]
the next goddamn [bleep]
who tells me I'm finished.
You [bleep].
You can all go [bleep] yourselves.
What? Sure.
Please welcome the talented voices
of Phineas and Ferb.
Go [bleep] yourself.
[bleep] you!
Meanwhile, Gob had arrived back stage
and was doing some advanced recon
for Mark Cherry...
-Where's the cocounut shrimp?
-...before his scheduled performance.
Especially if they could get it
with a bit of...
It was then that Gob noticed
the presence of a competitor
from his past.
Tony Wonder.
That lousy, failed magician.
Gob realized that where there was glitter
there must also be Tony Wonder,
waiting to make his magical re-appearance
so he decided to take advantage
of an unexpected diversion
and have a little fun by
wedging shut a panel on the podium
he knew Tony Wonder would pop out of.
You guys wanna see
a real failed magician?
Get down to the Opies tonight.
It's gonna be hysterical.
But, while Gob dimly remembered
the fun night,
he'd completely forgotten
the seven ambulances
that had arrived after Josh Abramson
had swung by to pick up
an old computer.
[Josh] One of them is Mark Cherry.
He's a singer.
[woman] Calm down. How many ambulances?
[Josh] Five, ten. Maybe seven at least.
[narrator]
That's how Gob found out his colony...
had checked into rehab.
Come on, you guys.
It's just...
a little alcohol poisoning
never killed anyone.
Actually, alcohol poisoning is responsible
for over four thousand deaths a year.
"Binge-drinking." Not cool.
♪ I mean come on ♪
Well.That's a drag.
I thought we were friends.
But, of course, they weren't.
And that's when he saw Tony Wonder.
[Tony] I'm here and I'm queer...
...come out of a speaker.
And now I'm in a speaker.
No one can stop us.
Wait, if...
If Wonder wasn't in the... podium,
then who's...
It was Marky, of course.
But moments earlier, and realizing
it was still too early to let him
out of the podium...
Lindsay headed to the bar
and was suddenly face-to-face
with Herbert Love...
...are we the only two people
who don't fit in
with all these Orange County phonies?
...and had no idea who he was.
They are a bunch of phonies.
I usually don't even go to these things.
And perhaps it was because
he reminded her so much of Tobias
when they first started dating,
that Lindsay flirted back.
-What's your name, princess?
-Cindy Feather...bottom.
Of the Laguna Beach Featherbottoms?
Are you trying to find out where I live?
And your favorite kind of jewelry.
Lindsay hadn't heard the word jewelry
in a long time,
but tried to stay strong.
How do I know you're not
one of these phonies?
The only phony I'm interested in...
is your phone-y number.
And, like Cinderella at the ball...
Lindsay really felt like a princess,
for a change.
But also like Cinderella,
she lost track of the time.
[explosion]
And that's when she was struck
with an eerie sense of deja vu.
Lindsay!
Oh God.
He blue himself.
Lindsay's attempt to create a disaster
for Herbert Love
was a complete disaster.
And as she tried to slip away
without drawing attention to herself,
she was once again approached by the man
whose name she never got.
Perhaps we can engage
in some sexual congress.
But that's a total give away, right?
What a wonderful sense of humor.
I'd like that very much.
Sir, the press awaits.
I thought you were sticking it to the man,
-not the other way around.
-Maeby.
You think he likes me that way?
No Mom, that's Herbert Love,
the man you're here to protest.
-[Love] ...the guy with the bomb
snuck up from Mexico. That's why I say,
we have to build a wall.
Oh no...
How could you not recognize him?
In fairness to Lindsay,
It was Marky's face-blindness
that led him to mistake this photo
for the candidate.
Why Lindsay failed to recognize
musical icon Nat King Cole
cannot be explained.
But he's so modern looking.
I didn't know it was the man
whose politics I'm here to protest...
I guess I was just having fun
pretending I had my old life back.
Well, we'll just be friends,
and I'm going to keep it light and fun
and not talk politics at all.
I can't believe you're such a sell-out.
Are you really gonna
whore yourself out like that?
I am not a whore.
-Yeah, you're a whore.
-I am not a whore.
I am still committed to my ideals
and to my Marky.
[Marky] Lindsay!
Lindsay! Lindsay!
Well, you certainly have a type.
Lindsay? Have you seen
a woman named Lindsay?
If you see a woman named Lindsay,
tell her to bail me out.
-[pitches voice low] I'll do my best, sir.
Thank you.
[growls] Taxi.
On the next Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences...
After the explosion,
Gob has a pivotal moment, as he realizes
he's lost his fiancée, his career,
his family...
I have no one in my life
who cares for me.
and his entourage.
["The Sound of Silence" plays]
[phone rings]
Great, and now my boss is on my ass.