[narrator] Michael Bluth had discovered
that a feature story about him
had appeared in a magazine.
Hi. Hello.
Hey. Where are you heading today, sir?
[narrator]
It was only available on airplanes.
Actually, I just want a copy
of your in-flight magazine Altitude.
This is ticketing.
You can get the magazine on the flight.
I get it. But I'm actually...
I'm in the magazine.
How many bags?
I'm not checking these.
Sorry, you actually
can't carry those on board.
Let me start over.
I am the star of Altitude magazine
this month.
Or quarter actually.
It's an April-September issue.
I just want a copy.
[narrator] Michael hoped the article would
generate interest in his housing business,
which had been going through a dry spell.
This, combined with some other misfortunes
had led Michael to sacrifice some
of his privacy
and move into the dormitory of his son...
Name one way we're different.
[narrator]
...with whom he'd always been close.
But as exciting as the news
about his magazine article was...
They're gonna be in seat backs today?
That's great news.
[narrator]
It was tempered by the intrusion...
Probably doesn't have it.
Tried finding a flight?
[narrator]
...of George Michael's other roommate.
Ever been on a plane, you [bleeps]
[narrator] It was the desire
to be closer to his son...
P-Hound was suggesting
that maybe we do a vote
to see who stays in the dorm room.
Right, then he's gone in seconds.
[narrator] ...that led Michael to embrace
the voting idea as his own.
We gotta do it.
-Not flying anywhere.
-Why do you have suitcases?
-Those are irrelevant.
-Not to me.
Okay.
[narrator] The suitcases were part
of a series of solutions
that Michael implemented...
It puts me in an awkward position.
Everyone's going to know
who voted against who.
[narrator]  ...to Salvage a highly fraught
voting scheme.
What if I vote myself out?
[narrator] As whenever he found a solution
to one problem...
Wouldn't that be a tie?
[narrator]  ...another problem emerged.
All right, new plan.
If it's two votes against me,
then P-Hound is being nasty...
[narrator] Then more problems...
Vote against P-Hound.
-[narrator] And so on.
-We all pack ahead of time.
Really pack a bag,
so it doesn't look rigged, you know?
[narrator]
So Michael can't be blamed for feeling...
I was mistakenly voted out
of a four-person housing situation
in a pack-first,
no-talking-after scenario.
Does that clear it up?
What do you mean by "mistakenly"?
[narrator] The mistake was not realizing
it was actually his son's idea...
-I voted against myself...
-...vote against himself.
[narrator]
...to get Michael to vote against himself.
Vote his own father out of his dorm.
But that leaves three other votes.
Michael.
-Can I get a magazine, please?
-No, I'm sorry.
They're actually for passengers.
We don't even give out nuts,
so we can't give you a magazine.
-Who wants nuts?
-I don't want nuts.
I want to just jump onto the plane,
grab a magazine.
Okay, sure. We just let people walk
onto the plane all the time.
Do you want a box cutter also?
Nice.
These guys are jerks.
I got your back.
[man] Attention passengers for flight...
Tell you what, give me a ticket
to your cheapest destination, please.
[narrator]
So, Michael found his seat...
with no seat back in front of him.
Hello. Hi.
Does each ticket entitle the passenger
to an in-flight magazine?
No, it only guarantees you a seat.
Perhaps I can ask
another passenger for one,
or if I'd rather, you can.
[narrator] Michael had to go back four
seats before someone would.
And Michael kicked himself
for a pose he thought
would express humility
to Sanjiv, the Altitude photographer.
Now the story of what happened
when the one man
who was holding his family together
finally let go
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice...
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development...
Fateful Consequences.
Michael was a man who, for years,
had threatened to leave his family
but had always stayed for his son.
But now he no longer had that excuse
nor anywhere to live
and he found himself with nothing to lose
in a town that he'd always imagined...
would be his destiny.
And for the first time
in many years,
Michael had hope.
George Sr. also had hope...
[Herbert] ...to build a wall...
[narrator] ...because he had purchased
a large swath of desert property
where his twin brother
was living with a bunch of weirdos.
Watch us make love?
[narrator] Yet despite making his brother
think he was purchasing it for him...
We're staying?
[narrator] He bought it so he could
low bid a government border wall project
he was hoping to build.
We offer to build it for 150 million
and we make up the difference
when we sell the land.
If you support the wall...
[narrator] Which is why he needed
to persuade a fairly right-wing politician
to make it a third point
in his three-point plan.
All I got right now is,
you want to reach into my pocket
to pay for your birth control?
I get to put my hand in your pocket
to put it in.
Yeah, but when I unveiled it
in Garden Grove,
I had to duck a woman's pump
and a mini pizza.
Oops.
[narrator]
So it was a big victory for George Sr.
-who'd been feeling emasculated of late.
-[cheering]
And aside from hating the wrinkles he saw
in the rearview mirror
around his eyes and brow,
George, Sr. was happy.
♪ All you need is smiles ♪
♪ Lots and lots of smiley smiles ♪
♪ All you need is... ♪
What the [bleeps] is he smiling about?
Hello.
Oh, we're doing a survey
for the US government, ma'am.
Oh, no, I'm a man.
I was just wearing this blouse
because I was driving, and I hate my arms.
What's the tape for?
Laying out border coordinates
for when they put up the wall.
You're not supposed to tell him
what it's for.
Well, he already mentioned the tape,
and he looks American.
Yeah, but he's in Mexico.
Wait. Guys, no.
Mexico starts back there by the gully.
Whoever told you that
is probably chomping on the maca.
So, what you're saying
is that on this side of the tape,
I'm in Mexico,
but when I come over here--
Whoa! We're gonna need
to see a passport, sir.
Pasaporte.
[narrator] George Sr. liked to make
men who disappoint him suffer.
But things change...
You really hurt my feelings, guys.
[sobbing]
-No touching, ma'am.
-I'm sorry.
[narrator] And George wasn't the only one
feeling the heat
of a rash decision about where to live,
for when Michael stepped out
of the air-conditioned airport...
Know a good place to live?
[narrator] He discovered something
about Phoenix he hadn't anticipated.
Dear Lord. [laughs]
-I'm making a new start.
-Don't touch that.
Oh! Mother of God!
Dear Lord! Whoo!
[narrator] So Michael returned
to the only viable place to live
he could think of
and began his new life,
cleaning up after his old one.
Buster.
No.
No, Gob.
[narrator] It was Lindsay.
-Michael Bluth was starting a new job
-[horn honks]
when he received a call
from attorney Barry Zuckerkorn.
Hello. Michael Bluth,
Residential Complexes.
[Barry] Hey, Michael.
-You're in real estate again?
-Sort of.
[narrator] Michael had tried
to leave real estate behind
and get a job in the high-tech sector.
However, I will tell you that
in my last position,
I had a company car provision.
We may have something
that can get you a car.
-Hey, Gare-Bear?
-Yeah?
I think we got an ostrich.
-Oh, God, grab him.
-What is it?
Now, with this car,
you may get some stares.
I'm used to a car
with some stairs.
[narrator] Albeit one that had trouble
negotiating low-hanging obstacles...
-[horn honks]
-[tires screech]
[narrator] Which is why he parted
with it.
I'm actually working in high tech,
but it does collide with real estate.
This is gonna be low.
Oh, I hooked it.
[narrator] Michael was driving a car
from a company that shows
every private residence in the country.
But it's also a company that won't let us
show the car that takes those pictures.
In fairness to them, it is their property.
-If you want to know the company...
-[man] You [bleeps]
[Michael] Save it.
We're just gonna blur it anyway.
[narrator] ...all you have to
do is "something" it.
Barry? Still there?
So, I got a really interesting call
from Ron Howard of all people.
He's directing now, apparently,
and wants to meet you
at his office in, get this...
Beverly Hills.
Why does Ron Howard--
Why does Ron Howard want to meet me?
His office didn't say,
and I'm a little busy
with a case of my own.
Want me to tell him
to go [bleeps] himself?
I can tell Ron Howard
to go [bleeps] himself.
I just can't do it now,
because I'm in front of a jury.
I will meet with him.
-You're in front of a jury now?
-And the looks I'm getting. Got to go.
Sorry, everybody.
I'm an attorney, too.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
I'd like the defendant
to reach over the gate,
open it from the inside
and enter the school property, please.
I can't reach it.
I can't reach the Chachi.
If he can't reach,
this trial's a breach.
Ooh, and that's what we call a law bomb.
That's a low blow, Loblaw.
A Bob Loblaw law bomb.
[narrator] As a client,
Barry was hoping for a better fate
than that of his own client,
Lucille Bluth,
who, while being an inmate
at the Orange County Prison
Ladies Internment Terrace Enclave
had recently been visited by a man
she thought was her husband.
Talk about the wall.
[narrator] And in retribution
to a brother who lied to him...
So we only did buy that land
for personal gain. Well!
[narrator] Oscar chose to lie...
-[narrator] With George's wife.
-Call me Father B.
[narrator]  And although too explicit
for an American audience,
the lovemaking was intense and beautiful
but for one small misunderstanding
that occurred during the afterglow.
No.
I mean, it's good
to be out of that sweaty old hot box
at the compound.
-No, this was amazing.
-Oh.
[narrator] And Oscar finally got more
information about his brother's plans.
We may need to have
a president ready to go
if something should happen to Lucille 2
while we're building the wall.
So we are building a wall.
Right where Oscar
thought he would be spending
the rest of his life.
[laughs] Turn him around three times,
put him in Fullerton.
-He won't know the difference.
-Fullerton.
You know, I think we should
send our son down there.
Give him some training,
show that he has a job.
Let him sweat a little.
Buster? No. I won't hear of it.
It could kill him.
I meant Gob.
Oh! Fine.
Yeah, send him down. I love that.
[narrator]
But not before an ominous warning.
But, you know, he has magical abilities.
He can handle a lot more
than we give him credit for.
I know.
What?
[narrator] In fact, Gob hadn't been
feeling magical at all lately.
Ever since he wasn't able to open
a secret compartment.
that held handcuff keys,
at a wedding to a religious girlfriend
he was hoping to escape from.
And all in front of homosexual
rival illusionist Tony Wonder.
With his own career in shambles,
Gobs understandably excited
to receive a call from his mother.
It's your mother. We're going to plan B.
Go see your father in the desert.
He wants you to prepare
to be president of the Bluth company.
Finally. I will not disappoint you, Mom.
I am the perfect person
to look out for this family.
[horn honks]
[narrator]
But earlier that day, it was Michael
who was entering the world
of show business,
as he arrived at Imagine Entertainment,
the modest film, television
and streaming colossus
of Brian Grazer and Ron Howard.
And he got his first taste
of how cruel Hollywood can be.
That's not very nice.
"Ankles" means "leaves"
in Variety, Michael.
Kitty Sanchez.
What are you doing here?
I work here. I'm a D girl.
No, I don't want to see them.
I'm not going to show you my [bleeps]
you pig.
It means "development."
I'm a movie executive.
I work for Ron Howard now.
[narrator]
And she'd proven as loyal to him
as she was to her former boss,
Michael's father.
But without
the quote, unquote, "benefits."
Do you have any idea
why Ron Howard wants to see me?
Believe me,
if I could think like Ron Howard,
I'd own the second largest building
in Beverly Hills.
[narrator] Only Jerry Bruckheimer's
building was technically taller.
But who wants to be south of Wilshire?
-Mr. Howard will see you now.
-Oh, great.
I'll take you to the private elevator.
Going to meet the big man himself.
[narrator] But first, Michael
would have to pass a few little Rons.
[woman] Michael Bluth.
-[Michael] Hey.
-[Ron] Hey, nice try, mister.
-We can't beat the original.
-That's what I said.
-Hi. Hey.
-Oh, Michael.
Hey! Thanks for coming down.
I'm finishing up casting this
Andy Griffith Show thing.
Hang on a second.
Are you guys finally making that movie?
I've been reading about it for 40 years.
Well, it's not a done deal yet,
but I want to talk about you.
-Yeah.
-Hey, let's go inside the LEM.
You want to?
Is this the one that landed on the moon?
-On a soundstage.
-Oh, right, from  Apollo 13.
No, 1969.
NASA did go to the moon in '71
but in '69, they weren't ready,
so they faked the whole thing
on the soundstage of  Gentle Ben.
Boy.
Me and my brother hid up in the rafters.
We seen the whole thing.
But I want to talk to you.
Okay.
For the last year,
I've been going to Phoenix.
Whoa. Hang on, now. Are you kidding me?
I'm a Phoenix....
I've never met anyone else in person
that also goes there. That's amazing.
That's the downside
of going to college online, huh?
Well, I've just got a sick aunt
down there.
-But...
-Oh, I see.
On the last flight,
I was flipping through the magazine,
and I...
-I saw something.
-No, not the begging photo.
I don't think you know this about me,
but most of my movies
are based on still photographs
that I find truly inspiring.
[narrator] It was true.
Splash was based on what turned out
to be a counterfeit Hockney
that Brian talked Ron into buying.
The Da Vinci Code
was from this photo.
You know Willow?
That was from a Soft 'n' Snuggly
coupon I got in the mail.
But a man who is passionate enough to beg?
Well, that's a character
whose story we really want to see.
I've been dying to figure out a way
to do something about the market crash
ever since my partner Brian Grazer
was tipped off
that it was three months away
from happening.
What's that?
But I never had a face to put on it.
Until now. You.
Your wife is dying.
You're trying to hold
your family together.
Oh, gosh, no.
My wife died years before any of this.
Oh, gee.
I think it's a lot more
fun if we see her die.
That is fun.
And by the way, then it's a fantastic part
for a leading lady.
In fact, my girl Rebel
would be great in that part.
Your girl?
Rebel Alley. She's an actress.
You know her.
[narrator] He didn't.
I do. Yes, of course I do.
Your girl, huh?
Well, we like to keep that quiet.
[narrator] Michael assumed "my girl"
was referring to his mistress...
I see why you're telling me in the LEM.
[narrator] ...but Ron was actually talking
about his daughter.
You probably think I'm terrible
for even mentioning her.
No, I'm not one to judge.
I'm sure you've all got girls here
in Hollywood.
Brian's got two boys.
[narrator] Michael was suddenly given
the great opportunity
to make something of himself.
You're a natural.
It could be a great movie.
It's a real chance
to show you guys off, too.
Us guys?
Well, it's about the whole family.
Them?
We're gonna need everybody's signature
on these releases in order to make this.
Although the real heartbeat of this thing
is the father-son dynamic.
Yeah. You know, Ron,
I don't know if I can do this.
We're not in a great way right now,
and it might not be worth...
Take a few of these cards
and really think about it.
-All right.
-I got a tough meeting coming up now.
How do you tell Ed Harris
that he's simply not a Barney?
[narrator]
And while Ed was getting some bad news...
Am I a producer?
[narrator] Michael got some good news,
which he promptly shared
with the family attorney.
They want me to get
the family's signatures,
especially my father's.
Sounds like your thing
went a lot better than my thing.
Except, I haven't spoken to them
for a long time.
I mean, since I...
Well, since my mom...
-Left?
-[camera shutter clicks]
Yeah, for prison.
You want to know what?
Frankly, I think Ron Howard
just wants to get a movie
for his girlfriend.
It sounds like Ron Howard is casting
with his [bleeps]
Well, it is hard to believe,
but I guess
they've all got their mistresses
up here in showbiz, you know?
It's like it's their God-given...
-Front?
-No, right.
-Calm down, everybody. I got it.
You think my dad would ever go for this?
It's very hard
to get a signature out of him.
It's like somebody,
a long time ago, said...
What if you never sign anything,
and say you don't have a signature?
-Just like you, Pop.
-You don't have a signature?
No. He's never given me one card.
Not one birthday card,
which is why his presents
are money orders, right?
I don't have a signature.
Oh!
If you don't sign, you will be fine. Hey!
Barry, I hear what you're saying.
My dad would never do this for me.
I'm gonna head back in
and tell Ron Howard to forget about it.
-Yeah, you're screwed.
-Yeah.
-Do me a favor.
-Okay.
-Bye, Barry.
-Tell Ron to shove his waffle iron--
-Oh!
-Sorry. Oops. Whoa, sorry.
-My fault. Looking at my phone.
-No.
That's not too embarrassing walking around
with photographs of yourself.
Well, it's part of your job.
You're an actress, huh?
Yeah. Actually actress
is an overstatement because--
Oh, thank you. I was just sucking
at this audition I went on.
It was one of these ridiculous
meet-cute cliches,
when a guy and a girl just bump
into each other, and they...
They fall in love.
God, you're handsome.
I got maybe a lucky hair day.
You're the beautiful one.
You have beautiful eyes.
My deceased wife had red hair.
Yep, garbage like that
and it's so unbelievable.
Like they never get each other's names.
Pretty stupid.
-Oops. Gosh.
-Oh. Ow!
-Are you okay?
-That really hurt.
I wish I'd done that well in the audition.
[Michael laughs]
Where's a movie producer
when you need one, right?
It was really nice to meet you.
Yes, you, too.
I'm a movie producer.
Sorry. I'm a movie... Here, I've got...
I got proof here, huh?
-You are a movie producer.
-Yeah.
Yeah, there's a part for a wife,
and you'd be perfect for the movie.
-[Michael] Huh.
-[laughs]
Do you like Scottish music?
With the screeching horns and the silly--
Yeah. I'm in a band.
I love it. It's great.
We're playing at the Ealing Club
tomorrow night.
Maybe you could come
and just check it out.
Oh, yeah? I don't even know what that is.
[laughing]
Sorry. That's funny.
I should have said, "Where?"
I know what it is.
No, it's on the top of that building,
but can you imagine driving that car?
No, I can't. No.
-[Gob] Get away!
-[horn honks]
Sorry.
♪ Get away, get away ♪
♪ Hey, I met a girl today
And her name is... ♪
[bleeps]
[narrator] Michael was unsuccessful
at finding a head shot with the name
of the actress he'd just met.
While Gob went to visit
the man they called Father B
in what had only recently
been declared Mexico.
Hello, Father.
Don't call me that.
What are you doing here?
-You and Mom talked about it.
-We did?
Oscar.
I'd have been earlier, but I had to go
to San Diego and loop back
because of that border ribbon,
which is new, and I wasn't expecting it.
It's fine. Anyway, Father,
You've got to give me a job
so I can be prepared to be president.
You gotta keep this "father" stuff
to yourself.
I can't have these people
think I raised a limo driver.
I'm not a limo driver.
I'm a gentleman honey farmer.
The only thing back there are my bees.
-Beans?
-No, bees.
-Peas?
-Bees.
Bees! Oh, bees!
The boxes fell over on the way
when I swerved to avoid an ostrich.
You've got to do something.
These people paid a lot of money.
They won't listen to me.
They've got CCD.
-CCD?
-Colony Collapse Disorder.
The guy sold me just really sick bees.
Don't worry. Dad, they're gonna hive.
They always hive.
[narrator] Usually by seeking out
a structure that most resembles a hive.
Bees. Wonderful bees.
It's okay.
[narrator]
Then George Sr. got some more bad news.
Hello, brother. Thought I'd find you
in a blouse and a beekeeper hat.
What are you doing here?
No. We can't be seen next to each other.
I'm Dr. Norman.
Well, if you don't want to be seen,
then you go in the sweat lodge.
You owe me.
Is that a fact?
Listen, you told me
the property was on the border.
It is 50 feet south of the border, Oscar.
Well, excuse me,
but they hadn't put up the tape yet,
and you lied to me.
You told me
you bought this property to live on.
No, you bought this property
to put up a wall.
I told one lie,
but I was going to share the money
with you.
Two lies.
And why do I think that you charge
more than $5 for lemonade?
Three small lies.
Now do me a favor. Just get in the tent.
Gob's getting rid of the bees.
We'll push the matinee to 3:00.
No, I'm sick and tired
of being in that hut
pretending to be you.
Maybe I should go out there
and pretend to be you.
So, goodbye, George.
This is the last you'll see of me.
I'm just gonna use the can
for one second.
[woman] There's two Dr. Normans!
[narrator]
On the next Arrested Development...
Fateful Consequences.
After collapsing yet another colony,
Gob makes a startling discovery.
My cave.
[narrator] And decides to investigate.
Why didn't you open?
[narrator] Only to discover someone had
wedged shut his secret compartment
on the day
he deserted his Christian bride.
"T."
Tony Wonder.