[narrator] Gob Bluth had just been told
by his father
to go to work for his younger brother.
Thanks for the birthday card
that I never got from you
for the last 40 years.
What the hell?
And even though Michael was the one
asked to do the favor...
What the hell?
...it was Gob who felt he had
a cross to bear.
I got right of way...
In fact, the long estranged brothers
were secretly competitive .
with one another.
No... No, no.
My right of way.
Okay.
-Gob.
-Michael.
Still, they reunited.
Hey, Gob.
Michael.
...happy to see each other...
Gob?
...at first.
Michael.
So, hear you need help
moving these memorials
-to the death of the housing market.
-[jaunty tune warbles]
That's a memorial to the death
of Pete the mailman.
I knew that.
I brought one, too.
Size of the man's heart.
I've just got to figure out
how to get it out of the car.
If I could remember how I got it in.
-That's not from your Christian magic act?
-"Christian magic act"?
If I were Muslim,
would you say "Muslim magic act"?
No.
But it is hard to imagine any Muslim
handcuffing himself to a glittery cross
and living to tell about it.
Yeah, well, the Christians
aren't so [beep] hot about it either.
Well...
Michael could see
that his brother was unhappy,
and that his life had not worked out
the way he had hoped.
Things are incredible for me.
I'm having an incredible year.
I am a movie producer now,
producing a movie.
So they've got me in
this enormous office.
Told 'em I don't wanna be driving
to Beverly Hills every single day,
so they put me in an enormous office
just over here.
Rental.
My personal life is off the charts.
I met someone.
Can't really give you any information.
Kind of famous-y.
Well, good for you. I also met someone.
Also famous-y.
Can't give you any information.
In fact, Michael didn't even find out
who she was until one night earlier.
Oh, my God.
I'm dating Ron Howard's girlfriend.
Although, he did have
some of the details wrong.
She's an actress.
You know her.
She was Ron's illegitimate daughter.
A fact unbeknownst to many.
Well, we kind of like to keep that quiet.
I can give you information
about your airless office
you're gonna be spending mornings in.
You know what I could go for
is some guac.
-You don't live there anymore.
-This heat...
makes me want guac.
Now the story of what happened
when the one man who was
holding his family together
finally let go...
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
Model home? More like model tomb.
Am I right?
Michael and Gob reunited
after a long time apart.
...meticulously maintained.
[beep]
There are some vultures.
I think they might still smell Pete.
If it wasn't for the movie thing,
I'd do it myself.
They practically sell themselves,
just got to bring the people in.
I'm ready to move in today.
-No, people other than you.
-I'm starving.
Starving? You won't find anything here.
They've been abandoned for...
Lindsay.
No, this...
Maybe Tobias?
It was John Beard.
Shall we?
Well, the value of these homes isn't
gonna go down if we don't sell one today.
Let's see if I can find a...
Do you have a bottle opener?
Great idea.
And after a few more drinks
and a little more depreciation...
Michael admitted he had a rival
for his girlfriend.
You don't have to worry
about Ron Howard.
He's not competition for you.
Really?
No, the guy's, like, 100 years old.
What's he going to do,
poke you in the eyes?
You're confused.
Ron Howard directed  Apollo 13.
You're thinking of Mo Howard,
the angry Stooge, been dead
for a quarter century.
That's good ,
cause the whole time I'm thinking,
"Unless she likes a guy who's funny..."
-Sure.
-That guy is funny.
The whole time, you're like...
"Is he gonna poke me in the eyes?"
Gob, I don't think that the movie...
It might not even happen,
because I don't think that
I can ask my son...
What happened between him and me
was very disappointing.
Don't need to tell me
about disappointment and sons.
Let's not forget Steve Holt.
I was talking about a son
disappointing a father.
Yeah, that does make it different.
Show him you're a big shot,
you don't need to live
in your son's dorm.
I just live in my parents' penthouse now.
Take him to the Ealing Club.
It's all show biz.
I used to hang out there all the time.
It's actresses and stuff like that.
I don't know if I could pick up the phone
and call him and ask him.
You know what, Michael?
I'll call him for you.
You'd do that for me?
It's the least I can do.
You've given me a new sense of purpose.
I don't want you to
get your hopes up.
When I said that these places
sell themselves,
I should have gone on to say,
you know, that...
No, they don't.
I mean destroying Tony Wonder.
I'm going to destroy his career
the same way he destroyed mine.
Gob was referring to an escape act
he'd performed
that had failed when the hidden
compartment that held
the keys to his escape hadn't opened...
...humiliating him in
front of his bride...
He's not coming back.
Her...
and all of Christendom.
Destroying Tony Wonder
is your sense of purpose?
I thought you said thanks to me...
He's performing
at a gay club tonight,
and I need you as my boyfriend
to help me get in.
I'm gonna say no, thank you.
Don't you think
it's a little inappropriate?
I am your brother.
You sound like my son.
Whom Gob had spoken to earlier that day.
Her name's Ann, by the way.
Hey, you remembered.
How about you and I
go to a magic show together?
I love magic, of course.
It'd be sort of a father-son thing...
at a gay club.
Well, technically a gay night
at a magic club.
Hey, you know what'd be funny?
If you pretended to be my boyfriend
so I could lock this guy Tony Wonder...
I don't know,
I don't think this whole thing
is a good idea.
Besides, last time we tried
to do something together,
-you didn't even show up.
-What about you?
I didn't even hear from you
for your entire childhood.
Then thanks for the birthday card
that I never got from you
for the last 40 years.
This was extra hard for Steve to hear
on his actual birthday.
So what do I owe you?
There you go.
That's funny, I used to
date a guy named Steve Holt.
Steve Holt!
Yeah, that's the guy.
Heck of a birthday
this is shaping up to be.
In fact, it was about to get worse.
And didn't you already try
locking Tony Wonder in his trick?
Yes, but that wasn't for revenge,
that was just on spec.
And it didn't work.
Besides, that was before I knew
he had locked me in my trick.
You still don't know that he tried to
lock you in your trick.
I do know, I have proof.
I went in that cave
and I found this.
We both know what that stands for.
Jesus.
No, that would be a "J".
This is a "T".
Tony Wonder was there in the cave
the night that I did my big illusion.
So, when I went yesterday to the cave
and I saw that this had
wedged my compartment door shut,
I knew that I'd been wronged.
Okay.
The only thing that
we know is that you
tried to lock Tony Wonder
in his trick first.
-Right? So you're even.
-No, no.
Because mine didn't work.
He got the last laugh,
which, in this case,
happened to be
the first laugh.
I don't understand why you can't
seem to follow me...
You've got a chance to make a life here.
I'm offering you a good job,
selling good homes,
making real good money,
and I'm not asking for anything in return.
What is this?
I'm asking for something in return.
This is for the movie.
For your life rights in perpetuity,
in the known universe and beyond.
Look at this.
What's that mean?
You're not gonna sign it?
No. I was just thinking that I should
have my attorney Bob Loblaw look at this.
-He doesn't need to.
-I'm fine with it.
It's boilerplate stuff.
-I'm gonna be in a movie.
-No, you're not.
Okay.
Gob was making good
on a promise
he had made to Michael...
I need to see you tonight.
...to talk to his son.
It's about your father and you.
Really, is he upset?
Do I seem like a clown to you?
I got it.
Do I seem like some
kind of a clown to you?
I got it, Uncle Gob. Just tell me where.
Meet me tonight at the Gothic Castle.
I will.
The Gothic Castle?
No, the Gothic Asshole.
-Yes, the Gothic Castle.
-I didn't say the Gothic Asshole.
You think they call it the Gothic Asshole?
-I said the Gothic Castle.
-It's the Gothic Castle.
Okay.
-I think you look amazing.
-I'll take it.
-Great.
-No, no.
The compliment, not the shirt.
So, as Gob readied himself
for a magic show...
Tobias began work on a show of his own.
to create the Fantastic Four  musical,
that he himself wrote and directed.
The goal is that we all get
a little outing
on the Cinco de Cuatro,
where we'll be performing it on a boat.
I hope no one gets seasick.
Tobias had been working
at Lucille Austero's rehab clinic
as a therapist
for some Hollywood notables.
-Hi, I'm Mark.
-From pop star Mark Cherry...
But, please, first names only.
Mark is my first name.
Cherry's my last name.
And Simon says, you're out.
No. No, Mark Cherry,
I was having fun.
I have a bit of a wit.
Well, I think we all recognize
this gentleman.
...to celebrity side-kick, Andy Richter.
I'm not Andy fucking Richter.
Correction...
the identical quintuplet brother
of Andy...
I'm Emmett.
...who has withheld the use
of his likeness.
Emmett who?
Richter.
Simon says, you're out.
But most notably of all...
he reconnected with a woman
-DeBrie!
-He'd loved and lost...
How are you?
So, you two know each other?
Only to find out he was
about to lose her again.
...there is no way you
can be her therapist.
And so Tobias found a way...
to be with the woman he loved.
I could direct, we could get
Mark Cherry to do the music,
and we can cast it with patients.
She was in the movie, The Fantastic Four.
I was in The Fantasticks.
And so it was decided.
And this'll make my stay shorter?
I'll get out of here a week sooner?
Well, sobriety is
the most important thing,
but we'll see how good the music is.
And so they set to work.
And even though DeBrie had some trouble
with the choreography at first...
Tobias knew she'd blow them away
with her show stopping number
as the Invisible Girl.
♪ I don't want to be invisible ♪
♪ I don't want to be invisible anymore ♪
Okay, good. Get out there.
All right. Okay.
I like this, too...
Where's Argyle?
She's choreographing.
Let's all do it too.
It's called the thinking man's squat.
[all moaning]
Go with her. Go. Follow her.
But if DeBrie was nervous...
Am I crazy...
or is this really good?
...it was nothing compared to
how George Michael felt
when he arrived to speak
with his uncle at the Gothic Castle.
which, that night, did resemble
the Gothic Asshole.
-Uncle Gob!
-Don't call me Uncle...
Actually, that's good.
That works here.
-Is my dad upset? What's going on?
-He's fine.
You told me he was upset about something.
I don't know.
I do know that your daddy
wants you to get your hot, little,
tight, little, hot ass
-right up there right away to see him.
-You had me come all the way here
to tell me my dad
wants me to meet him?
Those things are unrelated.
I'm trying to lock this guy, Tony,
into this gay magic trick.
And I just needed
believable arm candy...
I do know that your dad
is really upset with you.
He's upset?
I asked you that.
That was the first thing I asked you.
You're giving me these crazy...
Mad?
-God, what is that inky taste?
-It's my stamp.
-I'm sorry about that.
-No, that's okay.
I probably won't come back in.
I'm gonna go see my dad.
Yeah, because you're a good son.
Bit my tongue...
Now get out of here.
I never want to sleep with you again.
After successfully looking like
he'd had a fight with his boyfriend,
and knowing that Tony would
go into the closet
and pop out of somewhere else,
Gob proceeded to lock
everything he could find.
and Gob settled in
to watch his revenge play out.
[Tony] A magician has many secrets,
but there was one I was forced to keep,
by society.
"Don't talk to us," they said.
"Keep your hands to yourself,"
they also said.
[man] Magic is only for straight men.
[Tony] I don't want to look at you, son.
Just go to work.
Why can't you be like your brother?
Well, I'm here...
I'm queer,
and now...
I'm in a chair!
Did somebody say Wonder?
[narrator]
Nobody actually did that time,
but I think he got away with it.
Didn't expect to see you here.
Want to get a drink later?
And believe it or not,
it was this trick...
Now everybody's gay!
...that really brought
the crowd to their feet.
Although it was pretty easy
to figure out how he did it.
They started out gay.
You missed your cue.
Gob was having a drink with a man
he'd twice tried to sabotage.
Beanbag chair. I was wondering
what you were gonna pop out of.
Did somebody say "wonder"?
...ing?
I always try to stay one step ahead
of the audience.
¡Vamonos!
Come on, man. Timing, right?
Leave the mask.
Yeah, of course, mask.
Yeah, that makes sense.
I use a mask myself,
in my act.
You have to tell me how you do
that beanbag trick.
I guess, since you're a magician, too.
But not a word of this.
I did use a mask.
I put it on another guy
and I was in the beanbag.
That's why they put that sign
on the beanbag.
"Do not sit on this..."
And the magicians shared the secrets
of their ancient and mystical craft.
And also it's very hard to get out of
at the end,
when I appear.
So how have you been?
I haven't seen you since your "wedding,"
when you did the Jesus gag.
I guess you could say
I was a runaway groom.
It's okay, I know it didn't work.
It made the "Woops" column in Poof.
It's cool, though, man.
I've been there.
Your assistant
probably sabotaged you.
I don't even use one anymore.
I resorted to using my own legs
in the Saw-the-Lady-in-Half gag.
I even shaved them.
Want to feel?
Sure.
Wow, they are smooth.
Like a lady's.
I think.
You're funny.
Too bad we can't do this more.
I dunno if it'd be great
for my reputation
to be seen with
a fundamentalist Christian magician.
And he was suspicious
that Gob might not be gay.
Although, the fact
that he borrowed Tobias' car...
...with the license plate ANUSTART.
-That's me.
-...alleviated some of those concerns.
What the hell?
Let's do it.
And the next day, Tobias returned
to the model home.
Beard, I'm only here
to pick up my car keys.
Tobias?
Gob?
Good to see you, old friend.
What have you been up to?
Things are good, nothing much.
I'm a registered sex offender,
but things are good.
Yes.
And I'm working at
Lucille Two's rehab center,
the one she owns,
not the one she famously
went to 12 times.
Can we finish over breakfast?
I'm starving.
Is it finishing? Okay.
And the two friends caught up.
If I wouldn't have gotten arrested,
I wouldn't have ended up working at rehab,
and I wouldn't have
reconnected with my love.
True, I can't ethically ravage her body,
I have to leave that to time,
but she's just so much fun to be with.
I, too, am in a relationship,
but mine is purely
a revenge-based deal.
I plan on making this person
fall in love with me
and then destroying them
by breaking their heart.
How do you make someone love you?
Can you pass the mustard, please?
It's easy when you've got so much
in common. Last night, for instance,
we both got a case of the munchies,
and then we went out
and we stole these pies...
As it turns out, they did a lot
more than steal pies.
They had a raucous good time.
And then the candy
bean dish right here,
we made those at Color Me Mine,
and I know they're kind of cockeyed,
but they remind us both
of my crooked smile.
I'll tell you who,
but this person is sort of a celebrity.
Turns out my femme fatale
is a bit of a celebrity herself.
Well, looks like life is
going pretty well for both of us.
Except that I'm broke.
And I'm a sex offender.
Michael expects me to sell
these split-level death traps.
And how am I
supposed to do that?
I mean, there are no schools or libraries
or Internet or playgrounds
within 20 miles of here.
It's funny, I've been looking
for a place to live,
and that fills virtually every
parole requirement I have.
That's great.
When can you move in?
Duh! Now.
The other sex offenders
are gonna be so jealous.
And that's when Gob went from filling
one Sudden Valley house...
You know other people
with similar needs?
I have a list of men that could
fill every opening you have.
...to filling them all.
Let me get a shot of mustard.
That was all cheese,
but no mustard.
Gob didn't want  to look too into it...
by calling Tony right away.
[Tony] It's Tony... I'm not here right now
because I'm right behind you.
Made you look.
But how did I know you looked?
Because I'm right behind you!
[narrator] Although, he did seem
kind of into it.
[Tony] Made you look again.
Tony, it's Gob.
Man, does anybody ever fall for that?
Listen, I was thinking about you,
what a fun night we
had the other night.
So just call me when you get a chance.
Okay? All right.
[cell phone chimes]
-That was fast, you hot little... Hi.
-[Lucille] It's your mother.
You better start to build this wall,
pronto.
I tried with your father,
but he can't do it.
[narrator] The wall in question
was to be built
between the US and Mexico.
but without the resources to build it...
George Sr, had found a work around.
There's more wall...
And you know, it feels good
to be protecting our borders.
It's a heart project.
-We love America.
-Daddy!
God, he Steamboat Willied it.
He had.
[Lucille] You need to make it look like
major construction has begun on the wall.
I'm busy now.
I'm working with Michael.
What are you working on?
Dad made him give me a job.
I see, so he thought
it was a good idea
to have you two together.
Isn't that nice?
My God, is there anyone
there with half a brain
that can help me with this?
I don't know about half a brain,
but Tobias is living with me right now
and he's not very bright.
[narrator] And Gob set out to find a crew.
Who wants...
[feedback crackles, Gob wails]
[Gob] Hurt my ears.
Who wants to help me build a wall?
...to keep Mexicans out of America?
All right, all right!
Who wants to help me
build a wall for no reason?
It's a different wall.
[bleep]
-[bleep] Hey, thanks for--
-[feedback crackles]
This thing is loud!
And so he decided
to head to the border ribbon
to put in some
manual labor himself.
[Gob] I'll show everyone I'm not afraid
of the sweet sting of sweat in my...
...when he came across
a local maca picker.
You need help to make your sign stand up?
Yes. No!
I need to find some Mexicans
to help build this wall.
You should get the Chinese
to build your wall.
-We make great walls.
-That would be great.
-How can we make that happen?
-I'm Chinese. I know all Chinese.
-I hook you up.
-Well, that's--
-[cell phone chimes]
-That'd be great.
Would you get off my [bleep], Mother!
Well, if I wasn't sure
you were gay, I am now.
It's Tony. Hey, Tony.
Sorry I couldn't talk last night,
but I'd really love
to get together later.
This week, or maybe Saturday.
Say, five o'clock...
-Great.
-I'm thinking Little Ballroom.
Good? You sick of Little Ballroom?
I'll see you there.
Bye.
That was Tony.
My friend Tony.
She sounds wonderful.
No.
No, I'm gonna get revenge
on him
and destroy his life.
Her life.
Our... life.
Destroy our life.
That doesn't matter.
Who cares?
On the next Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences...
You're gonna have to work
with our new patient,
and good luck with her.
We call her the "B" word
from the "C" ward.
Or is it the "C" word
from the "B" ward?
Tobias gets some bad news.
Hello, Anus Tart.
And she never even
saw the license plate.
[theme music plays]