[narrator] Now the story of what happened
when the one man who was
holding his family together
finally let go,
and the separate journeys
that eventually gave them no choice
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
Lucille Bluth had been released
from prison
into a rehab center run by a fr-enemy
under the care of her son in law.
...as your therapist.
You look great.
That suit looks very hetero on you.
Well, thank you.
You look very hetero as well.
Now, how are you?
I'm as normal as blueberry pie.
So, write that down on a form,
sign me out,
I won't have to
go back to prison,
and maybe you'll find a new car parked
in your driveway.
[narrator]
The night before she went to prison,
Lucille discovered that her family
had been divvying up her stuff.
And after originally resisting
going to Lucille 2's rehab center...
That's the bitch that put me here.
[narrator] She soon found
the other inmates turning on her as well.
-She's trying to noodle-stab me!
-[shouting]
[narrator]
And later received a chilling reminder
of how a family can turn on its matriarch.
And soon she discovered
that her son in law worked at the rehab.
-That was fast, you hot little--
-It's your mother.
Hi.
Sorry, I thought you were somebody else.
I can't tell you who 'cause I'm dating
someone famous.
[narrator] But after seeking his help
on a wall project,
she got some disconcerting news.
I'm busy now working with Michael.
What are you working on with Michael?
Dad made him give me a job.
I have to fill these Sudden Valley homes,
which I'm almost done with, by the way.
So he thought it was a good idea
to have you two together.
Isn't that nice?
My God, is there anyone there
with half a brain
that can help me with this?
I don't know about half a brain,
but Tobias is living with me right now,
and he's not very bright.
Although he is working in
the rehab where Lucille 2 is.
Hire a crew and start the wall.
And not a word to your brother.
I'm getting a transfer.
It's time for Mama
to put on the old drunk act.
That was an act?
[narrator] And one slurred call later...
[slurring]
she was ready to have her son-in-law
release her into society.
Yes, well, it doesn't work that way.
We have to have a series of sessions,
and I have to swear in the best
of my professional opinion
that you have accepted
and made every effort
at thoughtfully reflecting
upon your weaknesses.
Yes! Write down that I did that.
Well, no, I don't work that way.
You don't work anyway.
This is your first paying job
in ten years.
Oh, no, no, this doesn't pay.
This is part of a work release program.
[narrator] It seems Lucille
wasn't the only one
that was using austerity
to get out of a prison sentence.
So it's your daughter you're here to see?
Yes.
Maeby.
The state of California thinks
that I'm a sex offender.
Don't worry about
what the state of California thinks.
The point is, we have a chance
to be honest with ourselves.
Fine. You don't look heterosexual
in that suit.
Sign the form.
Well, at least we have a dialog going.
[narrator]
But that would end by their next session.
Perhaps that's why they call this place...
Auster-ity.
Auster...
Fine. Well, if you're not going to talk,
I'm just going to write this up.
[narrator] Earlier that day,
Tobias had encountered a prop problem
with his action musical.
...one thing we could use.
A villain.
I was thinking the same thing.
Why aren't the Fantastic Four
fighting anyone?
Instead of just dancing around,
you mean.
It's like it's all Sharks and no Jets.
Then we would have a second act.
Lucia, right?
I mean, that's their foe.
Lucia von Bardas?
Have you guys ever even
read one of these things?
This woman is a villain.
You think I'm a villain, too?
My children are all waiting for me to die
so they can divvy up my stuff.
My Chinese gang mates
were getting ready to noodle stab me,
and even one of the guards
called me "Gangie"
and he was talking
about the monster movie.
He thinks that horrible monster
looks like me!
So fine, you want to call me a villain,
I accept it! I'm your villain!
Actually I was writing down
a casting breakdown
for the role of Lucia
for my Fantastic Four musical.
This was all about your stupid play?
I was about to cry for the first time
in 60 years.
I remember when the last time was, too.
I hid under Mama's porch
during a thunderstorm.
and I found the remains of my...
It's not a stupid play.
It's a musical.
And I have to debut it
on a boat at Cinco.
It's on a boat?
Take to the sea!
Yes, I'll sign everyone out
for the night,
but I guess I'll have to play
the old sea bitch myself.
I'm in.
Well, that's wonderful. I think we have
made a breakthrough today.
In the musical, not you.
Oh, God, no, there's miles of work to do
with you. [laughs]
[narrator]
Michael was visiting the woman he loved
and wanted to star in his movie.
hoping to head off any ill feelings
she might have
about this interaction with her father.
I'll do everything in my power
to make sure she
never dates you again.
-[narrator] Or this one.
-You are ruining my life, Ron Howard!
She likes small.
May I please have ice cream?
No, no, you are the Depardieu.
No sweets.
[narrator] Michael wasn't proud
of what he was about to do.
Hey, Lem, I can reach the ice cream
and, you know, in my family,
we play a game called
"If You Do Something For Me."
I will give you this Dove bar
if you do something for me.
We have Dove bars?
Tell me what you know
about this...
George Maharis.
Not much. He's old.
Is he older than me?
Few years. He looks like you.
[narrator] He knew this was not good news.
So, handsome.
[narrator] But unbeknownst to Michael,
it was actually this George.
George Maharis.
[narrator] Who'd come up
with the non-sullied name,
because he didn't want to be compared
to that George or that George
and soon found himself in the arms
of a woman
he had no idea his father was courting.
His Uncle Oscar was also
living as a George, his brother.
in order to satisfy
a recently discovered lustiness.
And after failing
to find Lucille 2 at home...
-[woman] Security.
-Lucille 2, please?
[narrator] But, of course, at Austerity,
this woman is Lucille 2.
-Hello.
-I want to be with you.
I have needs.
George, is that you?
Yes, this is George. Where are you?
I'm in rehab, you know that.
What's wrong with you?
Why don't I swing by,
and we can conjugate.
Let's do our business over the phone.
All right. Here goes.
I wanna pull your panties off
with my--
Real business, George.
I'd very much like to pull
your underwear off with my teeth--
No, at Cinco. We're getting on a boat.
We're leaving the country.
But what about love?
Easy. Gene Parmesan got photos
of Herbert Love
with some redheaded whore.
[narrator]
That's not what he meant by love.
I'm giving his wife a taste,
so he knows we know.
If he wins, we should be able to get him
to do whatever we want
with that wall now.
I'm not completely following
the wall story. Here's my problem--
-Hello.
-[man] Michael Bluth here to see you.
Send him up.
-[Oscar] With my teeth--
-Michael's here.
This is my chance to make sure he doesn't
get too cozy with Gob.
-Why?
-Bad things happen when brothers collude.
When can we have sex?
[phone beeps]
Thank you very much.
Hello, there. Thank you.
Wow.
This is a step up from prison.
How would you know?
You haven't come to visit me once.
Yeah. Sorry. I feel bad about that.
So you're here to make amends?
Because you know your mother
will always take you back.
And because I know
my mother wants me
to sign away any connection
to the family business.
[narrator] It was true.
The real George Sr. made it a condition
of the now four-favor family pact.
You know, your mother
is very hurt you haven't visited her.
It's like you have given up
on the family business.
-I have.
-Yes, but not in writing.
To protect all of us, visit her,
sign a little something
saying it's all hers.
-I just need a signature.
-I'm happy to help.
If you do something...
-for me.
-For me.
Yeah, I heard
that's been happening.
I'm happy to help you, honey.
Me, too.
[narrator] And that's how Michael
got his mother's rights to the movie.
But not right away.
And that's how Michael got
his mother's rights to the movie.
So happy to help.
Me too.
-So, everything else is good?
-Yeah.
You've talked to your sister, the radical?
Yeah, she's a redhead now,
and she's dating Herbert Love,
but other than her looks
and her belief system,
she's the same old Lindsay.
That's Lindsay in the photo.
I hear you're dating an actress,
who's also dating Ron Howard?
[laughs] No, no, no, no, no.
She is not dating
Ron Howard, Mother.
Ron Howard is her father, okay?
Your mind...
I did, though, actually find out
who she is dating.
George Maharis.
[narrator]
And that's when Lucille found a way
to keep the brothers from colluding.
George Maharis...
George. That's your brother's name.
George Oscar Bluth.
Yes, uh, George is
Gob's first name, yep.
[narrator] And Michael remembered
something else strange.
I probably should
have expected that.
[narrator] And then stranger.
[Michael] "Love each other."
Oh, that definitely sounds like Gob.
And he did say he was
seeing someone famous...
[narrator] And Michael remembered hearing
about that as well.
Me doth think he hath a lady.
Oh.
And they're both bit of a celebrities.
That is odd, because I'm also
dating a celebrity.
If I were you, I'd put a tail on him.
Get a PI.
Where the hell am I gonna find a PI?
Gene Parmesan, at your service.
[shouts] It's Gene!
He does this to me every time!
-What's he doing here, Mom?
-He's working for me.
Why'd you scream then?
I thought he was that guy.
[narrator] But Gob wasn't dating Rebel.
He was dating this man.
We're on.
And he definitely thinks you're gay,
right?
Don't worry, the only thing
I'm better at than [bleeps] women
is pretending I'm gay.
[narrator]
As it turns out, Tony was dating
the daughter of a Bluth family competitor.
Give me a little leg shave?
All right. You have to be careful.
If Gob finds out you're straight,
he'll use it to ruin you,
and I'll lose the 100 grand I stole
from Lucille Austero
to re-brand you as the gay magician.
[narrator] It seemed Sally Sitwell had
a secret also.
-Ow!
-Ooh. Sorry.
It's fine. And as long as we're recapping
things that we already know,
an inside source tells me
he's my ticket to Internet billions.
-Inside source?
-I didn't tell you that?
-No.
-That's new?
It's "in the bag."
[narrator]  He made that sound
a lot cooler than it was...
The Fakeblock thing
will scrub it away.
[narrator]
Because it was Tony that was in the bag.
It took a lot of restraint for Tony to not
pop out when he heard the word "wonder,"
but he was carried into the audience
before he could hear that
Gob wasn't actually gay.
[Tony] I don't want some Spanish guy
sitting on me...
Once I get him alone,
I get into his phone,
get his boyfriend's information,
hack into his software and make a fortune.
Ow!
How do you not know
how to shave a leg?
I've never done it before.
Anyway, he's halfway
to falling in love with me already.
I mean, he actually sounded excited
about seeing me tonight.
Just be careful.
Could be a house of cards.
[shouting]
-Caterpillar!
-Yep! There it went.
That's exactly what that was. Wow!
-Weird.
-Very weird.
Caterpillar...
and that weird fuzzy moth in the drain.
[narrator] It seemed Sam Sitwell's
daughter had two secrets.
Michael was borrowing the family PI
to catch his brother having an affair
with his girlfriend.
-This is the great disguise? Fry cook!
-No, no, this is my horrible night job.
In fact, I was hoping
you could drop me off
at Chicken Dan's when we're all done.
Chicken Dan's, huh?
That is embarrassing.
This from a man
who's driving around a mapping car?
You know, I don't even think
these things work.
That's why I rely on
these babies right here.
The old binocs.
Let's see if we can't find this target.
You know, the great thing about these
is there's no software to update. [gags]
-God, what are you doing?
-Sorry.
Oh! These binoculars make me nauseous.
Well, of course they do.
Why don't you just use the maps?
We're riding in
a satellite-linked mapping car.
[narrator]
Gob, meanwhile, felt pretty good
after foisting one of the Sudden Valley
homes on Tobias.
I have a list of men that could fill
every opening you have.
[narrator] He had successfully
filled all the others,
and was on his way to a date
with Tony Wonder.
Siri, where is the Little Ballroom?
[Siri] I have three matches.
I'm gonna need the gayest.
Did you say "the grayest"?
I need the gayest one.
I found three matches.
I've got to tell Michael
that I saw another map car.
He's gonna be blown away.
You don't see them a lot.
Looks like he's turning
into a parking lot.
My Little Ballroom.
Of course, yeah. She's got a kid.
He's acting like he's Father of the Year
or something.
I bet he's pretending Steve Holt is nine.
I just saw him. He looks 50.
[narrator] But of course,
Gob was at the wrong Little Ballroom.
I do not get this lifestyle.
-Gob?
-You're mistaken.
Hi, there.
-Michael.
-Yeah.
Look who's here, you.
Where is she?
First of all, that's very dated of you,
Michael.
"He's" don't like to be called "she's,"
and I don't know who this he-man is
that you're referring to.
No, no, it's a "she." My girlfriend.
That's who I'm talking about.
Rebel Alley. Where is she?
-Never met him.
-It's a she.
Nice try. Now what are you doing here?
You gonna meet her here
with her son maybe
so her son can play in the ball pit?
That's disgusting, Michael.
This is no place for a child.
I know what you do.
Mom told me you were bragging
about seeing somebody in showbiz.
Then I see a frozen dove in a freezer.
-That could be anything.
-It said "love each other"
-on the foot band.
-That does sound like mine.
Whose freezer was it in?
Rebel. Rebel Alley's. Nice try, Gob.
If I want to see bad acting,
I'll go see Tobias in
A Jew Comes to Dinner.
[narrator] But Gob wasn't acting.
He'd just forgotten that he had met
still partying Rebel Alley
one year earlier.
He's so cute.
[narrator] And Rebel returned home
to an unfortunate surprise.
She felt bad,
so quickly put it in a bag,
wrote down the species and location
from which she'd acquired it
and then one further caution.
It was a merry mix-up,
but neither of them knew any of this.
-I have no idea what you're talking about.
-Yes, you do. I got you dead to rights.
Dead to rights!
If ever we were
gonna have a fight, Michael,
this would be the safest place
to do it.
-[Michael] Great, let's do--
-[shouting]
...something that can fillet a chicken
and subdue an intruder.
Back to My Little Ballroom?
Yeah, this is the middle of their workday.
Hey, hey, come back here!
You son of a bitch, Gob!
You'll never catch me, Michael!
You have to find me, Michael!
Gob?
♪ Keep those balls in the air ♪
♪ Balls in the air ♪
Are we done?
I'm just surprisingly tired.
So tired and so not hurt.
I'm not the guy, Michael.
I thought you'd be proud of me.
I did what you said.
I filled all your houses.
Hang on. Filled 'em?
Every last one of 'em.
With who?
With sex offenders.
Hey, hey!
Gob, you're out of the movie!
[boy]
Thanks for ruining my birthday party.
[narrator] Gob went to win back the trust
of the man he was still hoping to con.
Hey, look--
Oh, my God. You're mad at me.
You stood me up.
[narrator] Although he quickly lost sight
of that plan.
And then I got in this fight
with my brother that didn't hurt.
-It was just a whole--
-Is that it?
Or is it because your boyfriend is 20,
and I'm nearly twice that?
You think that I care
that you're three years older than me?
No! I don't-- Check my phone.
Check my phone.
I don't need to check your phone.
Come in.
[narrator] But getting Gob's boyfriend's
contact information out of that phone
was the whole reason for Tony's charade.
The whole family hates me.
-Damn it!
-Which he remembered too late.
Yeah, damn it!
I even helped fill his stupid homes
with sex offenders,
and yet he still hates me.
Sex offenders need a place to live, too.
Yes! Exactly! That's what I always say.
It's, like, God... You get me.
You're an easy guy to get.
I can't go home.
He's probably waiting for me.
He's gonna be my boss?
He's the younger brother.
-How old is he?
-Forty-two.
Same! My younger brother's 42, also.
Same! But...
-I mean 32.
-Two.
-Thirty-two.
-Thirty-two! Same!
-Same! I was gonna say it.
-Same?
-I was thinking the same.
-That's so weird!
You thought 32 and then you said 32!
-Same.
Crazy!
Do you want a glass of wine?
I love wine.
-Red wine? Same!
-I love red wine! Same!
[laughs] It's, like, two same.
That's in-same.
[narrator] It turns out,
the guys had tons in common.
-That's so weird.
-...weird.
[both] Like...
the last time I went...
scuba diving?
Wow.
Captain Crunch...
Same.
[narrator] The hours melted away.
I guess I must have been...
[narrator]
And perhaps, pretending to be gay...
I don't know, 17...
[narrator] Allowed them the freedom
to speak honestly.
When I started saying "same."
Same.
That's the same time I got into magic.
You know, I think I got into misdirection
'cause I just...
Maybe I was trying to hide my feelings
or something.
I was just doing it to get out of gym.
Who's Jim?
No. Phys Ed.
-Jealous!
-[laughing]
-Kidding.
-Right.
Kidding.
-Ooh!
-Don't start--
-Popcorn fight.
-[laughing]
[choking]
[coughing]
It almost went down my throat.
-I'll get some water.
-Yeah.
[narrator]
And Tony had another opportunity
to get at Gob's phone...
and chose not to take it.
Gob also saw an opportunity to,
in some small way, sabotage Tony's act.
And he also chose not to.
Although he did
put the mask down his pants.
[both] Ah!
We were really thirsty.
I guess I should get going...
Yeah, I'd say stay, but I just feel...
I feel like we should take it slow.
I would definitely stay
and have gay sex...
normal sex with you, but...
Yeah, I would totally have
gay sex or whatever, but...
I just drank a lot of water.
I just had a lot of water, too.
I don't want to rush things.
Same.
Maybe we make a date
to do it another time.
and tonight we just...
We can just sit and talk.
[narrator] Gob had never said anything
like that before.
That would be amazing.
[narrator] And then he said something else
he'd never said before.
I have feelings for you.
I have feelings...
for you.
[narrator] The feeling was friendship,
but neither had ever experienced it.
All they had to do now
was avoid making any specific...
Why don't we have normal sex on Cinco?
Let's have normal sex on Cinco.
[narrator] I guess they figured they could
get out of it later.
I'm not sure why they said that.
[both] Same!
[narrator] On the next
Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
Michael gets back.
-Hi, Mom.
-Hold on.
Michael. What happened to your eye?
Is that from Gob?
Was I right about him?
No, actually.
Want to hear a funny story?
You're out of the movie.
Hold on, George.
I beg your pardon?
Did you say George? Is that Dad?
'Cause he's the one who told me
to hire Gob.
I actually owe him a call.
Hey, Dad, how you doing?
Yes, he did. With sex offenders.
You want to hear something funny?
You're out of the movie!
Want to hold for Mom? Yeah.
Bye.