[narrator] George Michael's
relationship with Rebel
began under false pretenses...
How does your privacy software work?
It's private.
...and a false name.
George Mi-- Harris.
Rebel would soon unwittingly
be dating George Michael's father...
I just put your name in for something.
...who was also operating
under false pretenses
as the producer of a movie
about his family
he didn't have the rights for.
It might not even happen
because I don't think I can ask my son.
What happened between him and me
was very disappointing.
As he'd been unexpectedly voted
out of his son's dorm...
-and forced to find a new home.
-[wand beeps]
-You take it.
-But you've got nothing in your luggage.
I wasn't supposed to
be traveling today.
It was voting,
there was a miscalculation.
Obviously, P-Hound's gonna
vote against you.
So, it was Gob who asked George Michael
to meet his father...
...while he too was operating
under false pretenses.
I'm trying to lock this guy Tony
into this gay magic trick,
and I just needed believable arm candy.
But the deception caused Michael to think
Gob was his rival.
Rebel Alley. Where is she?
And an out of control Michael
fought with his brother
even though he'd done nothing wrong.
I filled all your houses.
With who?
With sex offenders.
...or at the very most, one thing wrong.
But, in fact, it was George Michael
in his alter ego as George Maharis
who has become Michael's
actual rival for Rebel.
What if I told you that he and I
were twins?
Although twins turned out to be
an apt description.
Ironically, the UCI housing office
also thought George Michael was a twin.
They're twins, ugly.
We should sign them up for twin club.
And while those false pretenses
made it hard to be on campus...
it did get him a pretty cool room.
George Michael Bluth had
never been more popular.
He was surrounded by people
thrilled to be in his company.
They're out of root beer.
So I got you one with the last bit
of root beer
because I remember
somebody was saying,
George Michael likes root beer.
And as his business
was taking off...
Thanks a lot.
You guys don't have to do all this.
This was just a little
get-together for my girlfriend
to show her I'm doing well.
...so was his romantic life.
Hey, stop it!
That was the last
root beer snow cone.
I got that for him, Carlos.
Teach you for being
such a kiss-ass, Terry.
And it was an ex-Bluth employee
who was the most grateful to be
in his company.
-Want any of these?
-No, I'm fine.
You know, I really appreciate
you guys doing all this.
I just wish I understood...
why?
That's why!
Because you could ask us
why we do this,
and mean it.
The fact that you could be so
down to earth...
And look so young.
...while you're
starting this giant company.
You've created an opportunity many of us
thought we'd never have again.
See, that's the part
I don't understand, Carlos.
-You know my name!
-What's his name?
You're the kiss-ass, Carlos.
Guys, I'm gonna learn all your names.
-I promise.
-George.
And that's when he heard
what had become his name.
-What is all this?
-It's just a little surprise.
-You did this for me?
-Yes!
Well, they did it for me,
but only because they knew
I wanted to do something for you.
Maybe we could talk
without your friends.
These guys aren't really my friends.
I barely know their names.
I mean, I know Carlos, but...
only because of that old song,
"Carlos the Tickle Monster."
Wait, what song is that?
God, I knew he made that up.
But it did
help me remember.
Don't worry about these guys.
They're not listening to a word.
How about that kiss?
We need to talk.
[all] Ooh.
Now the story of what happened
when the one man who was
holding his family together
finally let go,
and the separate journeys that eventually
gave them no choice
but to come back together.
It's Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
Months before the party,
George Michael was
readying his dorm room for Rebel.
-Look, I got us a peace pizza.
-That's great.
-You gotta go.
-What'd you do with my stuff?
I've got a girl coming over...
Yet he still wasn't ready to let go...
-...of Maeby.
-It's not Maeby, no. But...
You have to stay away,
She's already trying to start Fakeblock,
-and I'm trying to stop her.
-You can't. It's our company.
-But it's not real.
-Could you please leave?
First you "F" me with Fakeblock, and then
kick me out when you have a hottie coming?
-I have roommate rights.
-You know what?
You voided your rights when you took
this picture of Maeby brushing her teeth.
-Not against the rules.
-Still a little weird.
But not against the rules.
-Well...
Know what?
This is no longer a peace pizza.
That is a war pizza.
Okay, that's fine.
Enjoy your war pizza.
The pizza hadn't even cooled
before George Michael had officially
gotten over Maeby.
Thanks for keeping
it down for my RA.
You were keeping it down, right?
You know what really
impresses me about you?
How little you try to impress me.
I aim to not please.
I just came from a dinner
with this right-wing politician
and his date,
who was an actual hooker.
-They sound like terrible people.
-They were.
So, wait, is this where
you conceived Fakeblock?
It was George Michael's first chance
to truly be unpretentious
and undo the big lie.
On the other hand,
she thought he was
an unpretentious software genius.
If she were to learn
that he was merely
a wood block player
with a heightened ability
to track the passage of time,
perhaps she would rightly feel
lack of pretension should be a given.
It was after second
23 that he said...
Yes, it was right in here.
-Wow.
-Yeah.
This is like making love
with the Wright brothers
in their bicycle shop.
I'm sure she just
meant one of them.
Hey, how about her knowing
they had a bicycle shop?
A little token...
And the next morning...
Listen, I got to go shoot a PSA.
I'll text you from the car.
No, don't...
-Action.
-Tweet and drive.
Yeah, that was good,
but it's "text."
And we need the word "don't."
[man] Don't Tweet and Drive PSA, take 19.
Don't make me do another one, Ron.
Did we get that?
That was a don't.
But upon returning to his dorm,
George Michael discovered that
P-Hound had officially filed a grievance
with the Student Housing office.
So P-Hound claims that George Michael...
Make a note of that,
that's one person.
I know.
Messed with his stuff
and stole some software thing?
Yeah, and George Michael claims
that nobody can live with P-Hound.
Somebody's got to go.
It's time for a vote.
We'll each get one vote.
That doesn't really seem fair,
you guys are obviously
gonna vote for the same person.
Right, because we're twins,
and we have no sense of ourselves
as individuals.
That's right.
Fine. We'll each get a half vote.
And the four men cast their three votes.
It's a tie...
One and a half
to one and a half.
The twins were proud to show that
they voted differently from one another.
We're gonna need a tie-breaker, ugly.
Fortunately, they were able
to bring in two more half votes.
-It's a tie. Two to two.
-...who also proved...
...they were capable
of having opposite opinions.
-Double tie! Yeah!
-Yeah!
To break the tie,
more members of Twin Club
joined the electorate.
A quadruple tie!
Which also jammed up the works.
-Yeah!
-Yeah! Go.
Maybe we should just bring in
a single person now.
You mean, like, not a twin?
Just to speed things along.
And perhaps it was that comment...
I guess one head's better than two.
Twin hater.
We've been dealing with twincists
like you all our lives.
...that united the voting body
into a greater cause
than expressing their individuality.
And with the exception
of George Michael's vote...
P-Hound
George Michael. George Michael.
George Michael.
George Michael...
-...and one other curiosity...
-Bender from Futurama.
I almost wrote that.
...it was a George Michael blitz.
George Michael and...
a half vote for
"George Michael, twincist."
See you later, twin hater.
I'm not...
And that's when he ran into...
-[horn honks]
-...his beeping uncle.
Uncle Gob, what are you doing?
I was in the neighborhood. I happened
to remember how much you love bologna.
So, yeah, I just...
I found this great ShopRite
and I thought, "You know who's
got to have a taste,
is young George Michael."
He didn't think George Michael
liked bologna.
He was trying to
correct a bad impression
he felt he might have made
with his nephew a few nights earlier.
My God, Uncle Gob,
what is this?
Can't lie to you, George Michael.
It's a forget me now.
I wanted you to forget
what happened at that magic club.
I was embarrassed.
If you don't want me
to tell anyone about it, I won't.
I'm such a fool.
I go to those things too quickly.
Really, it's just the age we live in.
Take a pill to forget your problems.
Take a pill to go to sleep.
And take a pill to
forget your problems.
Need an erection, take a pill.
Need to forget your problems,
take a pill.
Take a pill and your
problems are forgotten.
Take a pill.
What an age we live in.
It's great, isn't it?
What's with the suitcase.
I got kicked out of my dorm.
That was a freebie.
You in the market to buy a house?
It's a great time to buy.
I don't want to buy a house.
I don't have that kind of money.
Money? Ninja, please.
You don't need money.
With that Fakeblock
thing you got going
and your great credit rating,
we can put you in
a Bluth in no time.
Frankly, it wasn't the kind of risk
George Michael would take.
But then Gob said something
that changed his mind.
Plus, it would make
your dad proud.
I know that he's still really
disappointed about you...
-That I blew him off?
-Blew him off.
Boy, is he disappointed about that.
-I would love to say yes...
-Yes! There it is!
I got my much-vaunted yes!
Gob felt good.
He would be able to
prove to his brother
that he could actually sell a house.
George Michael felt good,
because he could prove to his father
that he did indeed support him.
And the residents
of Sudden Valley felt good,
because it turns out,
the very young-looking man
who drove down their street
that afternoon...
Hello, young man.
How young are you?
I'm good. How you doing?
No, how young are you?
I'm 22.
...was over 21,and they wouldn't
have to search
for a home that
was even more remote.
He's 22, but looks 16.
The Sudden Valley residents
wasted no time
in welcoming George Michael
to the community.
...welcome you to the neighborhood.
Thank you. Hi.
Hello again. Welcome back.
...every chance they got.
It's so nice.
It's my birthday.
It's everyone's birthday.
I wonder who this is from.
We said no clothes, Carlos.
A hat is not clothes.
A hat is clothes.
I wish I had something to offer you.
Here you are, guests in my home,
and you've gotten me
beautiful gifts.
Feels like it should be
the other way around.
[man] Football!
And it was during an impromptu
touch football game...
No, guys the play is dead.
The play is dead.
Maybe we can't play skins versus skins.
Tops versus bottoms?
...that the idea of a party
for his girlfriend came up.
Let's throw her a party,
Sudden Valley style.
And while George Michael was building
new relationships...
...privacy on the web, until now.
Maeby was building his new business
...and bringing in
more cash as a result,
her self-esteem growing every day.
Over the following days,
Maeby was able to
discreetly bring in
cash from Herbert Love
for services she got her mother
to unknowingly render.
Why don't you take him out to dinner?
-Put it on the family tab.
-Of course.
This high school senior was
working several jobs
We have to be discreet.
And she did her jobs well.
-What?
-Discreet!
She even started a Fakeblock office,
after trading shares to a new
silent partner for George Michael.
Stock options?
The shares turned out to be
useful for a lot of things.
-Hey.
-Hi.
You rented a little office.
I don't want you to see it yet.
Still setting it up...
with a little help
from a wealthy benefactor,
Lucille Two.
-Gangie.
-No, Lucille Two.
Austero?
-I don't know who that is.
-You don't?
Never met the woman.
She'll be the one driving
the stair car from now on.
-It was part of the deal.
-You gave her my car?
It's technically hers anyways,
because of the Bluth Company.
But I did get you her
1988 yellow Cadillac.
She only uses it to
and from hip replacements.
I guess that's only funny if you know
who she is.
And so, George Michael
was proud to invite Rebel
to see how successful
George Maharis had become.
and how many people
were eager to be in his company.
No, I'm fine.
He was tickling me in there.
-What is all this?
-Just a little surprise.
-You did this for me?
-Yes.
-But Rebel had other concerns.
-We need to talk.
[all] Ooh.
This is it.
This is the place.
Hope you don't find
it too pretentious.
Well, what happened to the old
"anything goes in the dorm"?
Well, I got this place instead.
You know, I guess I wanted to impress you.
I'm gonna get furniture, obviously.
The guys from Homefill
are coming this week.
That's not the problem.
No, that's not the problem.
Wrong house, buddy.
No, this is my son,
Lem Depardieu.
-Hey, baby.
-Hi.
Jacqueline still in the car?
You have a son?
-Yeah.
-Hey, Lem.
-Hi.
-How you doing?
I love kids. You want a Twister?
I was given four Twisters.
You should take one.
-Take a Twister.
-You know what, honey?
Do you want to give Mommy
some alone time with her friend?
-Maybe he could play in the pool.
-Yeah.
He'll be safe.
There's a hundred guys there.
-Make sure you wear your sunblock.
-Okay.
In fact, it was the folks in the pool
who were more at risk
of being near Lem
than he was of them.
Wow, what a great kid.
You know, when I said
I was not eager to have kids,
but I think it's
great that you have a son.
I have a spare room here
that the two of
you could stay in.
Or maybe you
could just stay in it.
He doesn't live with me.
He lives in France with his father.
He just visits March and April
during French pilot season.
But that's what I'm talking about.
I just don't want to get that serious.
Because you're seeing someone else?
No! I mean, yes,
I'm seeing someone else,
but I don't want to get
serious with him, either,
and you're telling people
in the neighborhood
that we're seeing each other.
What happened to the guy
who founded Fakeblock?
The guy who keeps things anonymous?
I can do anonymous.
I'm all about staying anonymous.
That's Fakeblock's mission statement.
And now you're asking Lem and me
to move into this house,
and it just seems all backwards.
Sorry.
Maybe it is backwards.
[tile shatters]
George Michael shared
his relationship problem
with the one other woman
he'd had a relationship problem with.
-That's ridiculous.
-Right.
You haven't told her
your real name, have you?
What? No, no. No, she still
thinks I'm George Maharis.
But she's dating another guy,
which is probably the whole reason
she's always saying
I'm moving too fast.
I take things too seriously.
I take things too serious.
I need to note which one of
those is correct,
because I sound like a horse's ass
when I alternate between the two.
I need to get my [bleep] together.
But the point is that I take things...
easily-breezily.
Well, a real serioush woman
knows what she wants
and moves quickly.
"Serioush" is nothing.
That's not a word.
Are you ready to see your office?
I have been. It's great.
I like it a lot.
I wonder if she's gonna think
we've been a little
lavish with money.
You know, is it too much?
But then to contradict myself,
I do think, at some point,
it would be good to get a second chair
just in case we have a guest,
but I'm thinking big picture.
Buddy, this isn't your office.
She's over here.
Welcome.
I'm a softie.
I hired the guy.
He's more like a mascot than anything.
Mort, where's my coffee?
Damn. Stupid Mort.
I know. It's okay,
just focus.
I'm going to take the cart
and show George Michael his new office.
-Speechless?
-How do I get back?
When Fakeblock hits,
we're going to have
to ramp up real fast.
This hangar can
hold over 500 nerds!
Maeby, we can't afford this.
And my software
isn't even ready.
Don't worry about that.
Just worry about being done in time
for the big public unveiling at  Cinco.
-I'll get the money.
-Isn't that in three days?
No, that's Cinco de Mayo.
Cinco de Cuatro is in two days.
We'll be doing it on a boat,
so I hope you don't get seasick.
You're doing the keynote.
You're responsible for all of this.
-Come on.
-What... No, I...
I think we...
All of this.
I think we should
delay the keynote.
I'd say yes, but I don't think we can
because of the sheer amount of money
that you have on the hook for it.
Maeby, you're fired!
And although Mort knew
he was going to be next...
there was nothing that could have
prepared George Michael
for what Mort would end up
leaving on his desk.
Maeby had just lost a big career option,
and as she was on her way to
visit a high school boyfriend
she was hoping to entrap...
-What are you doing?
-Long story.
I'm just here to see Lucille Two.
She ran into the current squatter
of the penthouse.
Come here for one second.
I need to talk to you...
about something very important.
Yeah... Uncle Michael,
I'm really sorry about that whole
"voting you out of the dorm" thing.
We never really meant it to...
I knew it.
I knew you didn't understand it.
I knew you guys were all...
'Cause I didn't...
I don't think I
explained it very well,
and it was very simple.
I made it complicated.
It was a four-person vote.
I voted against myself, so that P-Hound...
That's a way that scenario
would've worked out.
What I later realized is
there was another scenario...
Maeby. There was another.
-Yeah.
-C scenario.
-I really got to get going.
-Where you... Okay.
Before you do...
I need your signature here at the bottom.
Doing a movie about the family.
-Yeah. Is that still happening?
-What do you mean?
I gotta tell you, I think movies are dead.
Maybe, it's a TV show.
This girl that I'm dating, Rebel,
she's gonna be in it,
and she would never do TV.
You're dating Rebel Alley?
Yeah, I have a picture of us
to prove it.
I can't find it, but...
So, you're the other guy.
You know her personally?
Yes. I mean, that's how I know
that you were dating her.
Do you know the other guy
that she's dating?
And that's when she saw an opportunity
to get back at George Michael.
No, no, but I know it's over.
-She is dumping him.
-She's dumping him?
Apparently,
he was coming on too strong,
taking it too seriously.
She hates that.
-That what she said?
-That's what she told me.
Just kills it for her.
She wants it easily-breezily.
Well, that's informative.
I owe you. Thank you.
No, you don't.
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Don't knock, just...
Okay.
One second.
And so fortified
with Maeby's information that
Rebel was breaking up with
her other beau...
-Hello.
-Michael.
...Michael decided
to move things along.
I think that I've been coming on
a little bit too strong.
I got a lot going on,
I got the movie.
A bunch of stuff with the housing complex,
and I'm just...
I'm not gonna be pressuring you anymore.
I want to just keep it easy-peasy.
-Cool, totally.
-Yeah.
-Keep it loose.
And we'll have some
fun with, you know...
If the fun, you know...
Someday, one day,
it gets more serious,
you know,
then it does, and we...
We're walking down the aisle,
you know, and...
I'm saying it wrong,
because I get tongue-tied,
because I think that you...
are coming on too strong.
You know? Bugging me.
You want to come in?
No?
Yeah? Yeah.
It was the best
sex Michael ever had.
Was that fun for you?
No.
Are you gonna
take a photo of me?
No...
No, no, I've been
trying to get a signal.
But he wanted
a picture of them together,
which is why he grabbed the one he saw
from the photo booth.
Are you gonna call me?
If I'm in traffic.
Although he was
growing concerned
about how he was
going to keep this up.
Hey.
♪ I just stole this fair young miss ♪
♪ From a big shot, George... ♪
[bleep]
On the next Arrested Development:
Fateful Consequences.
Having found out the woman he loves
is also dating his son...
Michael places a call to the niece
who sent him there.
-Hello?
-You're out of the movie.
And George Michael finds himself
the subject of a lawsuit
over the ownership of Fakeblock.
Was it or was it not my client
who put up the initial seed money
for the block software
that served as the
underlying architecture of Fakeblock?
It was 99 cents.
[all] Times three.
Can I say something to my client?
Take to the sea!