[THE INK SPOTS'
"ADDRESS UNKNOWN" PLAYING]
♪ Address unknown ♪
♪ Not even a trace of you ♪
♪ Oh, what I'd give ♪
♪ To see the face of you ♪
♪ I was a fool ♪
♪ To stay away ♪
♪ From you so long ♪
♪ I should have known ♪
♪ There'd come a day ♪
♪ When you'd be gone ♪
♪ Address unknown ♪
♪ Oh, how could I be
So blind? ♪
♪ To think that you ♪
♪ Would never be
Hard to find ♪
♪ From the place
Of your birth ♪
♪ To the ends of the earth ♪
♪ I've searched only to find ♪
♪ Only to find ♪
♪ Address unknown ♪
♪ Honey child ♪
♪ I ain't even got
A trace of you ♪
♪ You know one thing? ♪
♪ I'd give anything
In the world ♪
♪ Just to see
The face of you ♪
♪ I was a fool ♪
♪ To stay away from you ♪
♪ And everything else
So long ♪
♪ I should have been
Diplomatic ♪
♪ And figured that someday ♪
♪ You'd be solid gone ♪
♪ Address unknown ♪
♪ Oh, how could I be ♪
♪ So blind? ♪
♪ To think that you ♪
♪ Would never be
Hard to find ♪
♪ From the place
Of your birth ♪
♪ To the ends of the earth ♪
♪ I've searched only to find ♪
♪ Only to find ♪
♪ Address unknown ♪
WOMAN 1 [ON TV]:
Yeah, that is some detail.
That is some Western detail
right there. Western detail.
Attention to detail.
He's even got the spurs
on the back of his boots,
and they're sharp.
WOMAN 2: Ha, ha. Love it.
WOMAN 1: They are.
The clock is gone on
this piece, Christine, so...
WOMAN 2: Oh, my goodness.
WOMAN 1: Let's just move on.
WOMAN 2:
Well, from time to time, people
make mistakes, that's okay.
This is our first Renoir
of the evening.
This is a heliogravure,
which is an etching.
It was hand pulled from
a copperplate in Paris in 1919.
We know this because
that's what it says on the back
where the certificate
of authenticity is located.
Just as lovely as can be.
Look at the soft, delicate
shading, very feminine.
This is a limited edition.
This is what you're looking for
if you are a Renoir fan.
WOMAN 1:
One hundred, oh, my goodness.
Right at the buzzer.
WOMAN 2:
Whoo! Good.
MAN 1 [ON TV]:
--of the few exceptions
is the African pancake
tortoise,
which has
a flat, flexible shell
that allows it to hide
in rock crevasses--
MAN 2:
--big swath of light
to moderate snow
from the Broken Bow area
down toward Kearney,
Hastings, Grand Island.
That is all moving
in our direction,
so I do think
around 7 to 8:00
the snow will become pretty
steady here across the region
with all this
moving on top of us,
and that's really gonna
knock down visibility.
And again, snow-covered roads
are gonna be definitely
likely this evening,
making it even slippier--
More slippery.
--than it is out there
at this time.
There's that winter weather
advisory in effect
till very early
tomorrow morning.
[♪♪♪]
The bitter cold weather
helped break up the compactions
we created this fall
in our fields.
[PEOPLE CONTINUE SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON TV]
SAUL [ON TV]:
Don't let false allegations
bully you into an unfair fight.
Hi, I'm Saul Goodman,
and I will do
the fighting for you.
No charge is too big for me.
When legal forces have you
cornered, better call Saul.
I'll get your case dismissed.
I'll give you
the defense you deserve.
Why? Because I'm Saul Goodman,
attorney at law.
I investigate, advocate,
persuade,
and most importantly, win.
Better call Saul.
Do you feel doomed?
Have opponents of freedom
wrongly intimidated you?
Maybe they told you
you're in serious trouble,
and there's nothing you can do.
I'm Saul Goodman,
and I'm here to tell you
that they're wrong.
It's never too late
for justice. Better call--
[♪♪♪]
[SLURPING]
JIMMY:
I think...
your brain is just
not all there yet.
If we were all held responsible
for what we did
when we were 19...
[JIMMY CHUCKLES]
I remember what it was like
to be a kid. Think back.
[CHUCKLES]
It's all--
Judge, what would you say?
These boys, 19, I can't--
I don't--
These three young men,
just like you.
Just like...
Psst.
Oh, to be 19 again. You with me,
ladies and gentlemen?
Do you remember 19?
Let me tell you,
the juices are flowing,
the red corpuscles
are corpuscling,
the grass is green
and it's soft,
and summer's
gonna last forever.
[JIMMY CHUCKLES]
Now do you remember?
Yeah, you do.
Ahem. But if you're being
honest, I mean, really honest,
you'll recall
that you also had
an underdeveloped
19-year-old brain.
Me, personally, heh,
if I were held accountable
for some of the stupid decisions
I made when I was 19,
oh-ho, boy, wow.
And I bet if we were in church
right now, I'd get a big "amen."
Which brings us
to these three.
Now, these three
knuckleheads--
And I'm sorry, boys,
but that's what you are.
--they did a dumb thing.
We're not denying that.
However, I would like you
to remember two salient facts.
Fact one, nobody got hurt.
Not a soul. Very important
to keep that in mind.
Fact two.
Now, the prosecution keeps
bandying this term
"criminal trespass."
Mr. Spinauzo, the property
owner, admitted to us
that he keeps most portions
of his business
open to the public
both day and night.
So trespassing?
It's a bit of a reach,
don't you think, Dave?
[JIMMY CHUCKLES]
Here's what I know.
These three young men,
near honor students all,
were feeling their oats
one Saturday night
and they just...
went a little bananas.
I don't know. Call me crazy,
but I don't think they deserve
to have their bright futures
ruined by a momentary, minute,
never-to-be-repeated
lapse of judgment.
Ladies and gentlemen...
you're bigger than that.
[BOYS LAUGHING ON VIDEO]
BOY 1: Kenny, are you rolling?
KENNY: Yeah, wait a minute.
Yeah, baby. Yeah. Ha, ha.
BOY 1: Tone it down.
Chill out, would you?
Hey, Miss Watson's
fourth period biology class,
this one's for you.
Watch and learn, losers.
KENNY: Oh, yeah.
[BOYS LAUGHING ON VIDEO]
KENNY:
Oh, God.
BOY 2:
Dude, where'd all the blood go?
BOY 1:
He's dead.
They suck it all out, dumb-ass.
BOY 2:
Awesome. Where do they put it?
All right, I'm through
the neck bone now, dude.
Kenny, get over here.
KENNY: I'm getting it.
BOY 1: Get a shot of this.
KENNY: Fine, fine.
BOY 2: Here, let me do it.
BOY 1: I got it.
All right.
KENNY: Oh, my God.
BOY 2:
You're sawing like a pussy.
Let me do it.
BOY 1:
Would you get off? Chill out.
BOY 2: All right.
BOY 1: Wait, wait.
Okay.
Wait for it. Wait.
[BOYS LAUGHING AND CHEERING]
Yeah!
Come on. Yeah, baby. Yeah.
BOY 1: Oh, my God.
BOY 2:
I dare you to stick your wang
in the throat hole.
BOY 1:
I will if you will, loser.
BOY 2:
All right, all right.
JIMMY:
What the hell
kind of math is that?
WOMAN:
Seven hundred per defense.
No, no, no. "Defendant."
"Dant."
Three defendants, 2100.
Which, by the way, bargain.
What I did for them.
WOMAN:
They going to jail,
ain't they?
So since when does that matter?
They had sex with a head.
Look, didn't nobody tell you to
try all three of them together.
One trial, $700.
You're gonna miss me.
You are gonna miss me because
it'll be a cold day in hell
before I do any more PD work
for this shitty court.
Sayonara, baby.
You have yourself a nice day.
[METAL DETECTOR BEEPING
AND WHINING]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[BREATHES HEAVILY]
[IN BRITISH ACCENT]
Law offices of James McGill,
how may I direct your call?
Yes, Mrs. Kettleman,
so good of you to return.
Actually, I don't have
Mr. McGill at the moment,
but I know he--
Oh, splendid.
Uh, unfortunately,
our offices are being painted,
and the fumes are quite horrid.
Could he meet you
and your husband at, say,
uh, Loyola's Café on Central?
Four o'clock it shall be.
Cheers.
[CHUCKLES]
[ENGINE STARTS]
MIKE:
Ahem. Three dollars.
Uh, I'm validated.
See the stickers?
Well, I see five stickers.
You're one shy. That's $3.
[SIGHS]
They gave me-- Look,
I'm validated
for the entire day, okay?
Five stickers,
six stickers,
I don't know
from stickers because...
I was in that court back there
saving people's lives, so...
Gee, that's swell.
And thank you for restoring
my faith in the judicial system.
Now, you either pay the $3,
or you go back inside and
you get an additional sticker.
Son of a bitch.
Fine. You win.
Hooray for you.
Backing up. I have to back up.
I need more stickers.
Don't have enough stickers.
Thank you. Thank you. Very nice.
Employee of the month
over here.
[CLAPPING]
Yeah. Hooray. Give him a medal.
Don't do anything, guys.
Just relax, all right?
Well, I'm just fuzzy as to why
you think he needs a lawyer.
I mean, Craig, the way you run
your office is beyond reproach.
Beyond reproach.
Yeah.
I'm a stickler,
you know--
He is. He's a stickler
with the money.
He's definitely a stickler.
Yeah. Yeah.
He's certainly
not guilty of some--
Certainly not.
He's innocent of any wrongdoing,
that's abundantly clear to me.
And frankly, I don't go looking
for guilty people to represent.
I mean, who needs
that aggravation, right?
Ha, ha.
Right.
Look, all I know is
what I read in the paper.
And typically
when money goes missing
from the county treasury--
And the number here is,
uh, 1.6 million?
BOTH:
Well, that's an accounting
discrepancy.
It's a discrepancy, absolutely.
But typically when that happens
the police look
at the treasurer.
And since
that person is, uh...
[CHUCKLES]
I just think a little
proactivity may be in order.
I just think I'd look guilty
if I hired a lawyer.
Yeah.
Actually,
it's getting arrested
that makes people look guilty,
even the innocent ones.
And innocent people
get arrested every day.
And they find themselves
in a little room
with a detective who acts
like he's their best friend.
"Talk to me," he says.
"Help me clear this thing up."
"You don't need a lawyer, only
guilty people need lawyers."
And, boom, hey,
that's when it all goes south.
That's when you want
someone in your corner.
Someone who will
fight tooth and nail.
Lawyers, we're like
health insurance.
You hope you never need it,
but, man, oh, man,
not having it? No.
[CHUCKLES]
Phew.
How, ahem, would we proceed
if we decided to, uh--?
Oh. Well, this is
a letter of engagement.
It's very simple,
straightforward.
Please, uh, read it closely.
But if you sign it, um,
I can get started on that
defense strategy of ours
this very afternoon.
BETSY:
Craig,
I think maybe
we should sleep on it.
Uh, sure.
Don't you think, Mr. McGill?
We should sleep on it.
Oh, please,
call me Jimmy. Heh.
Absolutely.
I mean, there's no rush.
Oh, and you know, Craig,
we gotta pick up the kids.
CRAIG: Oh. Right.
BETSY: At the...
BETSY: Yeah.
CRAIG: Yeah. Heh.
Well, uh,
we will be in touch.
Uh, thank you for the coffee,
and for the advice.
You're very, very welcome.
Oh. Um...
Here. Take this. It's, uh,
got my phone number on it.
BETSY: Yeah. Okay.
CRAIG: Got it.
The number is 9456, 0054,
4896, 0643,
and the expiration is 11, '04.
Okay, and the key word here
is "classy," all right?
Super classy.
Use only flowers
that look expensive,
but, you know, aren't.
Uh, and the note should say:
"Dear Betsy and Craig.
"Uh, best wishes from
your stickler for justice,
James McGill."
Okay? And McGill
is spelled M-C--
Well, run it again.
Well, no, no, no. It's paid up.
Run it again--
[SKATER YELLS]
[PANTING]
[WHIMPERING]
SKATER 2:
Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
Oh, my God, Cal.
Cal. Look at me.
Buddy, look at me.
Are you okay? Say something.
What did you do?
What did you do to my brother?
Why don't you look
where you're going?
He came out of nowhere.
You freaking hit him, man.
You ran him over.
[COUGHING]
You ran over my brother.
I got the whole thing on video.
It was an accident.
He didn't--
He didn't mean to.
Look, let me just-- Aah!
It's broke. Is it broke?
It's my leg.
You broke his leg.
Why you driving around
and not looking?
Driving around
breaking people's legs.
Okay.
Somebody call the cops.
Don't call the police.
Police.
JIMMY:
Don't call the police.
Call them myself.
Don't call the cops?
No.
How you gonna fix this?
What are you gonna do
to make things right?
I don't know, fellas.
What can I do
to make it right?
[SIGHS]
I don't know.
Five hundred dollars.
Five hundred bucks? Yeah?
Yeah.
Ow. What the hell, man?
Listen, Starlight Express.
I'm gonna give you
a 9.6 for technique,
0.0 for choice of victim.
I'm a lawyer.
Furthermore,
does this steaming pile of crap
scream "payday" to you, huh?
The only way that entire car
is worth 500 bucks
is if there's a $300 hooker
sitting in it.
Now, let's talk about what
you owe me for the windshield.
I'll take a check.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
[LATIN POP MUSIC
PLAYING OVER RADIO]
Chào cô, ladies.
[ALL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Chào cô, Mrs. Nguyen.
My, don't you look...?
My mail?
You work for people who have
sex with chopped-off head?
Was it in the paper?
I heard it from my cousin.
Why? Why you work
for these people?
Ahem. Just lucky, I guess.
Cucumber water
for customer only.
[WASHING MACHINE WHIRRING]
[SIGHS]
[BEEPING]
FEMALE VOICE:
You have zero messages.
[♪♪♪]
[ELEVATOR DOOR OPENS]
Brenda, looking good.
Nice 'do. Uh,
where's Lord Vader?
He's not quite ready
for you yet.
South conference room.
How about you wait out here?
How about I don't? Heh.
Oh, Sir Francis.
James.
Well groomed, as always.
Okay.
All right.
Keith, Karen. Yes.
You have meddled with the primal
forces of nature, Mr. Hamlin,
and I won't have it.
BRENDA [OVER INTERCOM]:
Do you want me
to call security?
It's okay, Brenda.
We got it.
JIMMY:
Hey, Jack.
Hey, Nate. Hey, Aaron.
What can we do for you, Jimmy?
I'm sorry,
it's this table.
Something just comes over me.
You can tell me what this, uh,
26,000 is supposed to be for.
That's money for Chuck.
Isn't that what you wanted?
A measly 26 grand?
Heh. Jesus, you're like
Peter Minuit with the Indians.
Throw in some beads and shells
while you're at it.
It's just a start,
there'll be more.
Unless you're gonna
just tear them all up.
And why was it made out to me?
Why not Chuck?
Can he make his way
to the bank?
I just assumed it was best to
have the money go through you.
We can do it
any way you want.
This isn't going away,
Howard.
What Chuck did for this firm,
and damn near single-handedly,
one-third of this place
belongs to him. Yeah.
What have you got,
12 chairs here?
Four of these chairs
are Chuck's.
You got five of these
light thingamajigs, uh,
one and two-thirds
are Chuck's. Yeah.
How many Danishes?
Six Danishes?
You can have all
the Danish you want.
No, no.
They're Chuck's Danishes.
And Chuck isn't greedy,
so he'll just take two,
plus $17 million.
In that ballpark.
I mean, we'll know
once we get the accountants
poking around here.
Until then, no more penny ante
checks designed to make it look
like Chuck still works here.
He doesn't.
He never will again.
It's time to do right by him
and cash him out.
So these are Chuck's own wishes
that you're conveying?
This is what's best for him.
So he personally told you
that it's his wish
to withdraw from the firm?
See, that would surprise me.
It's been nearly a year
since he set foot in here.
I'm just doing what's
in his best interests.
So am I. And I, for one,
believe he's gonna
lick this thing.
Until then, his office
is just as he left it.
His secretary
is still on payroll.
If Chuck can call this
an extended sabbatical,
then so can we.
He's that important to us.
You know what?
Let's let a jury figure it out.
Yeah. They're gonna
love you, Howard.
You're so down to earth
and relatable.
And you will atone.
It's Ned Beatty from Network.
For chrissakes, guys.
Jimmy.
I almost forgot.
This month's filings.
You can save me
the postage.
Weren't you listening in there?
Chuck doesn't work here anymore.
Think I'm gonna help you
establish a paper trail?
Jimmy--
Stop trying
to pawn that shit
off on him.
Jimmy.
You know, Jimmy,
sometimes in our line of work,
you can get so caught up
in the idea of winning
that you forget
to listen to your heart.
Give Chuck my love,
would you?
Oh, there you are.
Betsy, Craig.
BETSY:
Hi. Oh, Craig,
you need your own purse.
HOWARD: Did it work out?
BETSY: Yeah. Ha, ha.
It was very nice.
You look lovely today.
Oh, thank you so much.
[♪♪♪]
Couldn't you just--?
You know I can't.
[♪♪♪]
[TYPEWRITER CLICKING]
[THUDDING THEN
OBJECTS CLATTERING]
JIMMY:
Son of a bitch.
CHUCK: You ground yourself?
JIMMY: Yes, I grounded myself.
JIMMY:
You gotta stop
putting bacon on the list.
That cooler's looking like
a trichinosis stew.
Perfect timing.
[SIGHS]
Professor Brans Vogelson?
Mm-hm.
University of Helsinki?
Yeah, you're gonna have
to get that translated.
Into Swedish?
Finnish.
Finish, uh,
translating into--?
I'm sure there's someone
at UNM who can do that.
You do know I'm trying
to start a legal practice?
Vogelson's been working
on the effects
of electromagnetic fields
on zebrafish and--
Oh. Financial Times.
Yeah, I knew you missed it,
so I figured, what the heck?
Thank you. I know
it's expensive here.
That's not--
I don't expect you
to go out-of-pocket.
Go ahead,
reimburse yourself.
Thanks.
Hey, Chuck, uh, can you
not read that for second?
Can we talk?
Are you all right?
You look peaked.
I'm fine.
Please, just sit.
You're not in trouble?
Um...
You gotta cash out.
You gotta.
Again? Really?
There's no other way.
I know that you don't wanna
hear it, but you've got to.
You know I'm going
to beat this.
to get better.
Yeah, sure.
Well, then there's
nothing more to talk about.
I will beat this. Ergo, a falsis
principiis proficisci.
Meaning...
That's not--
Meaning.
That's the one about
false principles--
You proceed from
false principles.
Your argument
is built on quicksand,
therefore it collapses.
Yeah, you're not listening.
Ah. Fine. Let's take this
to its logical conclusion.
In order to pay out my share,
suppose my partners are
forced to liquidate the firm.
Then what?
That's their problem.
My clients are
out in the cold.
My cases are scattered
to the winds,
126 people lose their jobs.
What happens to your cronies
in the mailroom?
The assistants, paralegals,
the janitorial staff,
all of them
out on the street.
Your friend Kim, a promising
career, over and done with.
Hamlin owes you
everything.
You built that place
singlehandedly
while he was at Four Hills
working on his bunker shot.
Let's not exaggerate. I helped.
You helped.
[SCOFFS]
All the more reason
not to tear it down
just for a little bit
of cash.
Chuck, I'm going under.
Okay?
For the third time, with these
bull-crap contract counsel--
Bull crap?
Bull crap, pissant,
PD cases
at 700 bucks a shot.
Public defender work is some
of the best experience there is.
I just had a case, Chuck,
with three clients.
Uh, arraignment, voir dire, jury
trial, the whole nine yards.
You know what I took home?
Seven hundred bucks.
I might as well head down
to skid row and sell plasma.
You're representing people
who have nowhere else to turn.
Money is beside the point.
Money is not beside the point.
Money is the point.
I keep telling you,
have patience.
There are no shortcuts.
Do good work and the clients--
The clients will come.
Yeah, I know.
Okay.
Hand to God, I wasn't gonna
say this, but you are broke.
I can't carry both of us.
I've been trying like hell,
but I can't.
[CHUCKLES]
You're saying, what, you think
you have to provide for me?
I never asked you that.
You didn't have to ask, okay?
I've been doing my damnedest,
but the day of reckoning
is here.
Soon, Chuck, you're gonna
be out on the street
with all the electromagnetism
in the world
raining down on you.
Now, please, please,
picture that,
then tell me that money
is beside the point.
This is what has you
all worked up?
Yeah.
Jimmy, there's nothing
to worry about.
Here.
What is this?
A stipend. There's gonna be
one every week.
Eight hundred
and fifty seven dollars
from Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
I'm gonna pay him back.
Every penny.
I didn't wanna take anything,
but Howard was very insistent.
And I'm gonna pay you back too.
Hamlin was here?
It's not like I'm a recluse.
He put his cell phone
in the mailbox?
He understands
the situation.
He grounded himself?
Of course.
And the two of you agreed
that since, as everybody knows,
you're going back to work
any day now,
the firm should help you
make ends meet?
That's correct,
minus the sarcasm.
Hamlin's making you a chump.
I'm going to get better!
I'm gonna go back to work, and
I'm picking up where I left off.
[SIGHS]
Sorry.
Sorry, Chuck.
I understand that you're
trying to look out for me,
but you're missing
the bigger picture.
I got it.
Speaking of which...
Howard brought this.
He's concerned.
What?
You have to admit,
it could be confusing.
Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
James M. McGill.
That's my name,
I was born with it. I--
Still.
How about "Vanguard Law"?
Or "Gibraltar." Ple--
Wait, so I'm not supposed to
use my name on Hamlin's say-so?
What's he gonna do, sue me?
Nobody wants to create
an adversarial situation.
I'm sure Howard would
gladly pay the cost
of new matchbooks and so on.
It's simply a matter
of professional courtesy.
Chuck, whose side
are you on?
There are no sides.
But, Jimmy...
[SIGHS]
Wouldn't you rather
build your own identity?
Why ride on
someone else's coattails?
[SIGHS]
You wanna dance, Howard?
Let's dance.
MAN:
Yeah, backside on it.
Go.
You can get closer than that,
you bitch. Come on.
All right, here it comes.
There you go. Better.
How was that?
It's all right.
Here, take a look.
So tighter. Everything--
Tighter? What--? Tighter what?
I don't know, just stand
tighter. You know what I mean?
I don't know
what you mean.
That's a-- We can call that
a stylistic choice, I guess.
Hey, fellas. We got business.
How did you find us?
JIMMY:
I know. Eerie, right?
Whoa, come on.
Give me 30 seconds.
Could be the most profitable
30 seconds of your lives.
Let me tell you
about a young guy.
Actually,
he's about your age.
He lived a long way from here
in a town called
Cicero, Illinois.
And in Cicero,
he was the man.
I mean, when he strolled
down the street,
all the corner boys
would give him the high five.
All the finest babes
would smile at him
and hope that
he would smile back.
They called him Slippin' Jimmy,
and everybody wanted
to be his friend.
Slippin' Jimmy.
What the hell
kind of name is that?
Well, I'll tell you now.
Winters in Cicero are murder.
You guys, growing up out here
in the Golden West,
you don't know. Okay?
I'm talking cold that'll freeze
the snot right in your nose.
I'm talking wind that'll
cut through your jacket
and carve you up
like a Ginsu knife.
In fact, most folks in Cicero
were scared of winter.
But not Jimmy.
Jimmy would
wait around all summer,
and when September
finally rolled around,
and he'd feel
that first cold wind
come sweeping
off Lake Michigan,
he knew it was coming.
Was it Christmas?
Was it Kwanzaa?
Better.
It was slip-and-fall season.
As soon as
it was cold enough,
he'd find a nice, smooth
patch of ice.
State Street was good,
Michigan Avenue was better.
He'd pick his spot,
wait for it to get busy,
then he'd walk out
on the ice and boom.
He would biff it so hard
people would come running
from five blocks away.
Yeah, but did he collect?
"Did he collect?"
Slippin' Jimmy had it dialed in.
One good fall,
he'd clear 6, 8 grand.
That'd keep him in
Old Milwaukee and Maui Waui
right through Labor Day.
Eight grand?
Eight grand.
Now, see, I look at you guys,
I see potential.
The skateboard's a nice wrinkle,
that makes it a year-round gig.
Clearly, you know how
to take a header. Right?
But I gotta ask you,
your best day ever,
how much did you clear?
Six hundred and thirty.
[CHUCKLES]
Six hundred and thirty bucks?
Was that for one fall?
Two.
Two falls in one day?
[JIMMY CHUCKLES]
Even at your age,
that's gotta hurt.
True that.
All right. Well,
I got a job for you.
How's 2 grand sound?
Two grand for one hit?
One hit.
Plus you get to learn
from the best.
CAL: Nice boat.
JIMMY: Yeah.
Discrete, like a stripper pole
in a mosque.
Forget the boat.
Look at the car.
You know what that is?
I don't know, a station wagon?
It's a Mercury.
A 1988 Mercury Sable wagon.
Remember it. Burn it into
your brains, you got it?
It's a Mercury Sable wagon,
sure.
JIMMY:
Close your eyes.
What color is it?
Brown.
No, it's medium sandalwood.
Keep your eyes closed.
How does
the license plate start?
BOTH:
Four.
JIMMY:
Give those gentlemen
a gold star.
Betsy Kettleman's her name.
Every weekday between 2:25
and 2:50 she comes through here
on her way to pick up her kids
at Kit Carson Elementary.
You need a place where
she's gonna slow down, right?
Yeah.
All right. Well, there you go.
She slows down,
she hangs a right,
you come shooting out of there
and do what you did to me.
You go ass over teakettle,
you make it
a blue-ribbon special.
When she gets out of the car,
you're suffering
Saint Sebastian, right?
You're the hammer.
You get in her face, you scare
the bejeezus out of her.
Give me your phone.
It's kind of busy here,
don't you think?
Yeah. Witnesses are good.
Witnesses are pressure,
all right?
Now, once you've got her
good and rattled,
then you call for an ambulance,
but really you're
calling for me.
I'm number one
on your speed dial,
next to your weed dealer.
You call me,
I hotfoot it over here.
I just "happened"
to be driving by.
I stop to see
what the trouble is,
and this is
the important part,
you don't know me.
We've never met. You got it?
Sure.
Okay.
Now, I'm Mrs. K's white knight.
We go mano a mano.
You light into me, okay?
Get nasty.
No touching,
leave the hair alone,
but otherwise,
you know, open season.
Yell, stomp,
call me a douche bag.
I'm gonna play it cool, give you
back some of the razzmatazz,
and once she's seen
the fireworks,
you fold like a lawn chair.
Happy ending.
When do we get our money?
After.
"After."
You get paid
when I get paid.
I'm the rising tide
that raises all dinghies.
Now, pop quiz.
What's the car?
Mercury Sable wagon.
Baby-poop brown.
Okay, do you know me?
No.
Damn straight.
Go with God.
JIMMY:
Well, I'm just glad
I happened to be passing by.
Happy to be of help, Betsy.
May I call you Betsy?
Ahem. Please, call me James.
Oh, the kid will be fine.
Don't worry.
He just got his bell rung
a little. I'll handle that.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no.
I wouldn't think of, uh,
taking your money
for this, so...
The embezzlement case? Yes,
I'd be happy to talk it over.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, shit.
Two-minute warning.
Got it.
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[PEOPLE SHRIEKING
AND GASPING]
Oh, my God.
MAN:
What happened?
WOMAN:
Call 911.
LARS:
Oh, my God. Cal. Cal.
Look at me. Are you okay?
Buddy, say something.
Cal, look at me.
Come on already.
What is she doing in there?
She making a sandwich?
Where's her sense
of responsibility?
What?
Hey! What the..?
Funny to run into you,
Betsy.
I was just, uh,
strolling the neighborhood.
You were in an accident?
Oh, that's...
[SIGHS]
Come on.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
Yeah.
LARS: She took off on us.
She what?
It was textbook, man.
We were diamonds.
But then she just took off.
Okay, wait. She hit and run?
That's what I'm saying.
She bailed and wailed.
Okay, just stay where you are.
I'll come get you.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
No, no, no. Screw that, man.
We're following her.
JIMMY:
You're-- How are--?
You're following her how?
LARS:
We got our ways, yo.
JIMMY:
Okay, okay, okay.
New plan. New plan.
You do know me.
I'm your lawyer. You got that?
I'll meet you
at the school.
No, she's way past the school.
She hooked a left on Juan Tabo,
now she's coming into
Holiday Park.
Okay, stay with her.
When she gets where she's going,
wherever that is,
don't do anything.
Wait for me.
Wait for what?
You haven't been right even
once. Slippin' Jimmy, my ass.
You fell into the honeypot, kid.
You get it?
Hit-and-run is a felony.
So what?
"So what?" So more money.
He says we fell
in the honeypot.
He says more money.
So, what do we need him for?
Cal, Lars, whoever--
Oh, damn it.
Come on, come on.
[LINE RINGING]
CAL [ON RECORDING]:
Do it, do it, do it.
Son of a bitch.
Come on. Come on.
Hey, your leg.
Oh, I'm gonna do this one.
Okay. Hey. Hey. Yo, hold up.
Ah! Ah!
Hey, yeah, you.
What is the matter with you?
You hit and run.
You ran him over.
You felonied my brother.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Habla English.
We call-- We call la policia.
La policia gonna be pissed.
I see you hit him.
You see that windshield?
You did that.
I did that.
CAL: You did that to me.
LARS: Now you pay.
CAL:
Make with the dinero.
Dinero?
Sí, righteous dinero.
[WOMAN AND LARS
SPEAK IN SPANISH]
Okay.
Yeah, that's what
I'm talking about. Okay.
Let's go.
CAL: Is that money?
LARS: Yeah.
Watch the step.
Watch it. Watch the step.
[♪♪♪]
Where are you?
Holiday Park.
Mrs. Kettleman, Betsy,
what are you doing here?
Hit-and-run?
That's very serious.
I can mediate.
I represent their parents, so...
Come on, come on.
[♪♪♪]
Open up,
officer of the court.
Open up
in the name of the law.
Good afternoon, this--
[♪♪♪]