[KNIFE SLICING AND CHOPPING]
[MAN HUMMING]
[SIZZLING]
ABUELITA [IN SPANISH]:
Mijo! Mijo, are you here?
[IN SPANISH] I'm in the kitchen.
LARS: It's really messed up.
ABUELITA:
Mijo, I don't know what to do.
These boys,
these boys...
Hey, hello. Habla English.
Hey, are you the son?
Ow.
Grandson.
Listen, I was driving,
and suddenly there was a noise.
She hit him while driving.
I think I hit him.
My leg.
Grandma, don't worry.
It's all right.
Oh, my God!
But they're so angry!
The crazy old biznatch
ran over my brother.
It hurts so bad. It hurts
so bad. It hurts so bad.
You see? He's hurt.
Look at that.
Yeah, it's this one.
She broke his leg,
then she stood on the gas.
That's a hit-and-run.
She felonied me.
That's a felony.
We got the whole thing here.
[IN ENGLISH]
Okay, hold on.
Let me talk to her.
Start talking.
Good.
[IN SPANISH]
Grandma, everything is okay.
What is happening?
Aah! I need to lean on you.
He can't put pressure on it.
ABUELITA: I didn't mean to...
It's definitely broken.
CAL:
Es muy mal for my leg-o.
LARS: Lean on this.
Isn't your show starting?
CAL: It really hurts.
Why don't you go upstairs?
They say I'm in trouble.
CAL: Dude.
There's no problem.
LARS: Yes, sí, problema.
And now dos problemas.
CAL: Aah!
Dude.
Everything's all right.
I'll take care of it.
Turn it up so you can
hear it, okay? Really loud.
CAL:
I don't know
what you're saying, man.
Dude. Dude.
We got a real problem here.
Yeah, sí, problema.
[ABUELITA MUMBLING
IN SPANISH]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Hey, amigo, what're you gonna do
about this leg situation?
I really need a doctor.
Doctors ain't cheap, yo.
It's gonna cost.
Either you or her,
somebody's gotta pay.
[IN ENGLISH]
You want money?
Yes.
Yeah, damn straight.
Hit-and-run? It's no joke.
What are the cops gonna say?
Cops? They coming?
[STAMMERS]
Yeah, maybe.
That's up to you, man.
They could be looking
at this tape.
It's all up to you.
[GRUNTING]
You called her "biznatch"?
I didn't--
Whatever. Hurry. I'm hurting.
Show us the green,
or la policia
is gonna come
and take Granny away.
She's gonna go to jail.
You want that?
That's right.
Play it smart.
Okay, good.
So let's talk dollar amounts.
For what you did-- Unh!
Uhh!
Unh!
No!
Biznatch.
[♪♪♪]
[PEOPLE SPEAKING
IN SPANISH ON TV]
[THUDDING NEARBY]
[THUDDING CONTINUES]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[IN SPANISH]
What's happening?
Nothing. Everything's okay.
Are those men
still here?
They're gone.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
I'm in trouble, right?
No, everything is all right.
They're not going
to bother you again.
What's that on my carpet?
I spilled salsa.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Abuelita...
I'll help you.
No, no, no,
I'm almost finished.
You're missing your show.
Oh...
Are you sure?
Let Mijo take care of it.
You're a very good boy.
Listen, don't forget
to use club soda.
Yes, yes, don't worry.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[PHONE DIALING]
[IN ENGLISH]
Hey, get over here.
Yeah, my abuelita's.
Bring No-Doze, and tell Nacho
to bring his van.
[SIGHS]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[♪♪♪]
Open up, officer of the court.
Open up in the name of the law.
Good afternoon, this--
[PANTING]
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Showing hands.
I'm relaxed. Okay?
Um, non-threatening.
You move,
and you're dead.
Got it.
Seems to be
a misunderstanding.
Is there by any chance
a Betsy Kettleman here?
Not sure
if this is a situation
where I should or should not
look you in the eye.
Now sit.
Who are you?
Are you with
those red-headed scumbags?
My name's James McGill.
I'm an attorney.
Uh, I got a call
from some clients,
something about an accident.
I did not get
any details.
When I saw some skateboards
in your front yard, I assumed--
[DOOR OPENS]
ABUELITA: Mijo!
Mijo, who's this man?
Is he with the others?
No, no. He's as salesman.
Grandma, I'll take care of it.
Where are you going?
I'm going to grab
the club soda.
Mijo, I can still see
the salsa you spilled.
You can't let it dry.
Grandma, I will get
the club soda, I swear.
Trust me. Please,
just go back upstairs.
Okay. But I don't
want that to dry.
Because once it dries,
you can't get it out.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[IN ENGLISH]
Talk.
I'm gonna make
an educated guess
what happened here.
My two clients, Frick and Frack,
the mopheads,
were in a simple
traffic accident.
A minor fender-bender.
Maybe they were
on the wrong side of the street,
or they didn't look both ways.
It could happen to anyone. Heh.
My clients, exhibiting
extremely poor judgment, uh,
followed your grandmother
to this delightful,
well-tended home.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Now, at this juncture,
I am deducing
that they said or did something
that crossed a line,
and you,
with some justification,
you put them in their place.
[SIGHS]
Based on the salsa stain there,
could've gone a couple ways.
The bottom line, not to be
morbid, but if they're dead,
um, I'm guessing
that I'm, uh...
I'm gonna-- Yeah, I'm gonna go
with glass half-full here
and say they're not.
My point is, if they're
still alive, why kill us?
Because of a misunderstanding?
Our own stupidity?
Why mess up your lovely
abuelita's place? Ha, ha.
Why jump to the nuclear option?
See, I'm saying keep it simple.
I will collect
my moronic clients,
and, poof, we are gone.
Neither you
nor your lovely abuelita
will ever lay eyes on us
ever again.
Guaranteed.
Signed, sealed, and delivered.
Assuming, you know,
that they're still breathing.
Wow.
You got a mouth on you.
Thank you.
Get up.
That way.
That way?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Why not?
[MUFFLED MUMBLING]
So I should, uh,
cut them loose?
Ow!
It was him!
It was all his idea!
No, no, no!
TUCO: You shut up!
Say what?
He wanted to scam you.
He said we could clear
2 grand easy.
[♪♪♪]
TUCO:
You punking me?
[GUN COCKS]
Are you punking
my abuelita?
He hit his head. He doesn't
know what he's saying.
[CAL GRUNTING]
No.
TUCO: For what?
For what
are you getting 2 grand?
It was for going after
your grandma.
For taking a header
over her car,
and then for bracing her.
It was him, I swear.
It was the lawyer.
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
[BOTH MUMBLING]
Who are you?
Why are you after me?
I can explain.
You're gonna laugh, it's so--
I'm a lawyer. Check my ID, okay?
I was running a scam--
On my abuelita?!
Not on your abuelita.
Not on you.
There's a woman
named Betsy Kettleman.
I mentioned her. She's married
to Craig Kettleman,
he's the treasurer
of Bernalillo County.
I wanted his business.
He stole a million and a half
bucks from the county.
He's gonna be indicted
for embezzlement any day now.
That's a good case for me.
A lot of publicity.
I'll get my name out.
Anyway, I thought
if I had these two
run their little skateboard
hustle on Mrs. Kettleman,
I could, you know,
rescue her.
Come in, throw some oil
on troubled waters,
and get their business.
That was the plan.
But it turns out
your lovely abuelita,
she drives a car that's a whole
lot like the Kettle-mobile.
So these two geniuses ran their
little stunt on the wrong one.
So joke's on me. Ha, ha.
Simple as that.
[♪♪♪]
Where's he going?
What--?
Talk to me, okay?
Who do you think I am?
What is he getting?
I was running a scam
to get a client.
I made a mistake,
that's all this is.
Oh, jeez.
You don't need--
That's not--
I'll talk, okay?
Tell me
what you want to know.
Who do you think I am?
Hey, use your words, okay?
[SNIFFS]
You know what I smell?
I smell lies.
I smell pork.
No, that's not necessary.
TUCO:
We know you're with the heat.
The question is, who?
Local, FBI, DEA?!
No, I'm a lawyer.
Just reach in my pocket
right now. Right there.
[♪♪♪]
Truth.
That is the truth!
I'm a lawyer! I passed the bar!
Ask me anything!
Not contract law--
I'm down at the courts
every day.
People know me.
I'm a known quantity. I am.
[JIMMY GRUNTS]
I'm-- I'm Special Agent
Jeffrey Steele, FBI.
FBI?
FBI.
I'm undercover, okay?
You got me.
I'm the tip of the spear.
Releasing me
would be the smart move.
You hear that shit?
I told you the business
was too good.
I knew it.
I told you.
Can I?
Okay, uh,
Special Agent, uh, Steele?
Jeffrey A. Steele.
Okay, Agent Steele,
what business are we in?
Business?
You're investigating us, right?
For what? What did we do?
What do we sell?
Drugs.
What kind of drugs?
Uh...
It's Title 21,
Schedule II through Schedule V,
including Part B.
That's what we call them
down at the Bureau.
The task force is designated
Operation Kingbreaker--
Kingbreaker?
That makes me the king!
Whoo-hoo!
Can I?
All right.
The next words out of your mouth
ought to be the truth.
You understand?
Uh-huh.
Who are you?
I'm James Morgan McGill,
a lawyer trolling for business.
That's the truth.
Now, you find a Bible,
I'll swear on it.
What about, uh,
Operation Kingbreaker?
I made it up, okay?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I don't know you.
I don't want to.
Uh, this was a mistake.
It's my mistake. Okay?
I take full and complete
responsibility, but...
I don't know
any of your names,
and I got a bad case
of face blindness.
You let us go, we're gonna
forget this happened.
Guys, we're gonna forget, right?
Nod your heads.
[MUFFLED MUMBLING]
Okay.
So if you'd just let us go...
I just--
We wanna just go home.
I say cut him loose.
He said he was FBI.
He admitted it.
You had your wire cutters
on him.
He would've said anything.
You really see the FBI hiring
those two flaquitos?
Maybe.
Croaking a lawyer for
no reason is bad business.
He goes away, someone's
gonna come look for him.
They walked
into my house.
They disrespected
my abuelita.
They called her "biznatch,"
and they just walk?!
Uh-uh!
What about the lawyer?
He's giving respect.
Okay.
"James M. McGill,
a lawyer you can trust."
[♪♪♪]
I know how to find you,
James McGill.
Understand what I'm saying?
Yeah.
[GRUNTING
AND MOANING]
Up.
Okay?
Take him back
to his car.
Thank you. Uh, this is good.
This is right. Thank you.
NO-DOZE:
Come on.
[SKATERS YELLING]
What-- What about them?
NO-DOZE: Come on.
JIMMY: Yeah, right.
[SKATERS CONTINUE
YELLING]
[SKATERS SCREAMING]
NO-DOZE: Yo, where you going?
Wait. Can I say something?
NO-DOZE: Where you going?
Can you let them go?
Just let them go.
Are you stupid?
They don't deserve to die.
I put them up to it.
I don't deserve to die,
but they don't either.
I'm gonna skin them
like javelinas!
Forget about them!
They're insects!
Hey, think about their mother.
I spit on their mama!
She is a sweet little lady.
She's a widow.
She works hard,
all day, every day,
just like her mother before her,
from dawn till dusk,
scrubbing the floors
of rich people.
She needs a cane to walk,
you know.
She's got arthritis,
and still she works every day.
What? For herself?
No, for them. For these two.
Her boys,
they're apples of her eye.
You say
they don't deserve her?
Maybe so.
But they're all she's got.
Now, you turn them inside out,
I want you to think about
what happens to her.
That's on them. They should've
thought about that.
When I was at
your abuelita's place,
you were gonna let them go.
The way I see it, that's because
you're tough, but you're fair.
You're all about justice.
That's what I'm saying.
Justice.
These two shit-for-brains,
these big-mouths?
You already beat
the living hell out of them.
You think they're ever gonna
forget today? Never.
Ten years from now,
they're still gonna be
crapping their Jockeys.
It's not enough.
Okay, okay.
Then let's talk
proportionality.
They're guilty.
Agreed.
Now you have to decide,
what's the right sentence?
Like a judge.
Ever hear of
the Code of Hammurabi?
Let the punishment fit
the crime? Eye for an eye?
Eye for an eye.
You want me to blind them.
No, no.
All they did was trash-talk.
So I cut their tongues out!
Wait. See, I'm advising...
that you make the punishment
fit the crime.
"Punishment
fit the crime."
Colombian neckties.
I cut their throats,
and then I pull their lying
tongues through the slits!
Biznatch!
Or you could give them
black eyes.
Black eyes? Ha-ha-ha.
That ain't nothing.
That one there, holmes?
He already got
a black eye, fool.
Stop helping.
Or you could sprain
their ankles.
Sprain?
They're skateboarders, right?
That's how they
run their scam.
They can't skate,
you hit them where they live.
I ain't spraining
nothing, bitch.
I'm gonna break their arms,
then I'm gonna break their legs.
Arms? When did we get onto arms?
I'm cutting
their legs off.
We could go that way, but
we were talking about breaking.
We're heading
in the wrong direction.
Okay.
Break their legs.
How many legs?
Two. They got two legs.
One leg, each.
One leg each?
One leg each.
Total of two legs.
Hey, look, they can't skateboard
for six months,
and they're scared of you
forever.
You show everybody that you are
the man, but that you're fair.
That you're just.
[SKATERS GRUNTING
AND YELLING]
One leg each.
That's tough,
but it's fair.
All right, lay them out!
I ain't got all day!
It's hotter than shit
out here!
[SKATERS SCREAMING]
Quit moving!
You're only gonna make it worse!
[BONE CRACKS
THEN SKATER SCREAMS]
[TUCO LAUGHS]
Look! Hell, yeah! Hell, yeah!
He said he had a broken leg,
now he's got one for real.
You, tell your mama
you're sorry, bitch.
Other one.
Hey, look, it's backwards.
[TUCO LAUGHS]
Check it out. I'm gonna
do this one real clean.
[BONE CRACKS
THEN SKATER SCREAMS]
[TUCO LAUGHING]
TUCO:
Whoo!
[CAL & LARS SCREAMING]
Walk home now, bitch!
Shut up! Shut up!
[♪♪♪]
[SKATER GRUNTING]
Here you go. Here you go.
Easy, easy. Save your breath.
You are the worst lawyer!
The worst lawyer ever!
Hey, I just talked you down
from a death sentence
to six months'
probation.
I'm the best lawyer ever.
Oh! Oh, my God!
[CHA-CHA MUSIC PLAYING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[BREADSTICK CRACKS]
[BREADSTICKS
CONTINUE CRACKING]
♪ Cha-cha-cha ♪
Could you--?
Uh, could you, um--?
I'll be right back.
[VOMITS]
[CHUCK HUMMING]
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
Ground yourself?
Jimmy, did you ground yourself?
I don't think
you grounded yourself.
Jesus.
Jimmy, you didn't drive
like this, did you?
Oh, no.
[♪♪♪]
No. I knew it.
[GROANS]
[GROANING]
[CHUCKLES]
Chuck.
Coffee?
Yeah, thanks.
You're gonna have
to take it black.
Out of milk?
Oh. Sorry.
Why are you
in that space blanket?
You brought your cell phone
in here last night.
It was
in your pants pocket.
Oh.
Sorry about that.
Where--?
Uh, where is it?
Outside.
I threw it out the door.
[GRUNTS]
How did I get here?
Your car's not outside,
so I'm assuming taxi.
[GROANS]
Right, uh, the bartender
wouldn't let me drive.
Why are you
in that space blanket?
I told you, you brought
your cell phone into my house.
Chuck, uh, did you...?
Chuck, did you read this?
Read what?
Uh, this bill,
did you read it?
Emergency room bill.
I may have glanced at it.
It fell out of your pocket.
Hey, Chuck, listen.
I know how this looks.
I'm down to my last dime,
and suddenly
I'm paying for broken legs.
But it's not that, I swear.
This represents
a good thing, ultimately.
Okay.
I'm not backsliding.
This isn't Slippin' Jimmy.
Fine.
Take off the space blanket,
will you, please, Chuck?
It helps.
Take off the space blanket.
I didn't do anything wrong.
It has nothing to do with that.
It was your phone.
[SIGHS]
Take off the space blanket.
Why?
Take off the space blanket,
Chuck.
Come on.
Take off the blanket.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Thank you.
Front yard?
Yeah.
Uh, do you have any idea
where it landed?
No.
[SIGHS]
WOMAN:
No.
No. No. No.
What do you want?
Not to starve to death.
What do you say?
You got something for me?
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[SIGHS]
It's showtime, folks.
[♪♪♪]
[DOOR BUZZES]
GUARD: Clovis, lawyer.
I'm gonna kill him.
Your Honor, I'm very sorry.
I'll never do it again.
Say what?
Just...
Your Honor, I'm very sorry,
and I'll never do it again.
Okay, Mr. Pearson.
Up you go. All right.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I told you a suit, remember?
You want to look sharp.
That's a loaner, okay?
I need it back. Let's go.
Petty with a prior.
Kid took a slice of pizza.
The parents are a train wreck.
There's no food in the house.
He was hungry.
Petty with a prior.
Come on.
You're light on stickers.
JIMMY: Come on.
Five dollars.
You serious?
You got four, you need five.
There's four 90-minute stickers.
You've been here
six hours and five minutes.
It takes ten minutes
to walk down here.
Five dollars, or you go
get another sticker.
This makes you feel
real important, huh?
Not enough stickers?
More stickers?
[♪♪♪]
It's showtime, folks.
It's showtime.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Petty with a prior.
Prior will stay on his sheet
for life.
Petty with a prior.
You're overcharging him.
That lady up there?
She shorts me every time, okay?
This is not a me problem,
this is a you problem.
[SIGHS]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
It's showtime.
It's from a movie.
[♪♪♪]
GUARD:
Hey!
Okay, hold it.
Petty with a prior.
Misdemeanor shoplifting.
Meet me halfway.
Petty, with a prior.
Ugh. I can't do it.
Petty with a prior.
Okay, how about this?
I plead the kid to the sheet.
You give me
a continued sentence.
He gets six months.
If he's still clean,
you file for a dismissal.
Come on. This is how
you want to spend your time?
You can have
the rest of these.
[GATE BUZZES]
GUARD:
Berger, lawyer.
Mr. Berger, we've met
before, haven't we?
Mr. Edison,
like the inventor?
I'm James McGill.
I'll be your lawyer.
Doesn't matter.
Judge has gotta see your mother.
Well, do you know anybody
who looks like her?
No, an uncle won't do it.
Okay, so a fire was started.
We all know that.
Freezing, shivering,
as she is now.
In fact, wrote a book about it.
To make some cookies.
But because you--
Given her this name--
You can see that this man--
Chose--
A bonehead move.
[♪♪♪]
You're like a troll
under a bridge.
"You must have the stickers,
or you won't pass."
Troll alert here. Don't feed it.
[SLOW POP MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Chào cô, ladies.
[WOMEN SPEAK
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Good evening, Ms. Nguyen.
No mail.
Hey, Vicki, Maggie.
[WASHING MACHINE WHIRRING]
[SIGHS]
FEMALE VOICE:
You have zero messages.
[SIGHS]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Customer.
What?
For you, a customer.
Waiting now.
Uh, sure, sure.
Give me a minute.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Welcome, welcome.
My office is being painted.
Excuse the temporary, uh,
quarters.
Wow.
Cozy.
Just me.
[CHUCKLES]
Tuco freaked you out, huh?
It's cool.
He doesn't know I'm here.
So, uh...
what can I do
for you?
I've been thinking
about what you said
out there in the desert.
Those people that
you were trying to scam,
how much did they steal?
Um...
North of a million
and a half bucks, I think.
So they have a million
and a half bucks somewhere.
In what, cash?
I don't--
Why are you asking me?
I'm gonna
rip them off.
Oh.
I like ripping off
thieves,
because they can't go
to the cops.
They have no recourse.
Hmm.
You point me at where
they have their cash,
I'll pay you-- Uh, what do you
call it? --a finder's fee.
Call it 10 percent,
100 large.
Wha--?
Why would you
come to me for that?
You already tried
ripping them off.
I'm gonna finish
what you started.
I wasn't trying to rip them off.
I just wanted their business.
Okay.
[CHUCKLES]
I don't know
where their money is.
Smart guy like you
can figure it out.
Find out what I need to know,
nobody gets hurt.
We rip them off,
easy money.
Look, I'm a lawyer,
not a criminal.
[CHUCKLES]
You are shitting me.
I crossed a line.
I made a mistake.
I'm not doing that again.
Not ever.
I got between you and Tuco.
Think you'd be here now,
I kept my mouth shut?
And I appreciate that.
I owe you.
And if you're ever in trouble,
God forbid, legal trouble,
I will be there 24/7
as a lawyer.
What's your angle?
No angle. Heh.
And I'm not saying
anything about this to anybody.
As far as I'm concerned,
you're a client,
this is a consultation,
and everything you just told me
is privileged.
You rat, you die.
And that too.
Yes.
For when you figure out
you're in the game.
I'm not in the game,
I-- I promise.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
[♪♪♪]