[PHONE RINGS]
Wallenda here.
[DOOR BUZZES NEARBY]
Yeah.
[OBJECTS CLATTER,
DOOR CLOSES]
Name?
Charles McGill.
Client visit.
[PEN WRITING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[PRISONERS SHOUTING]
[DOOR BUZZES]
Here's Johnny.
Heh, heh.
Hey, I knew you'd come.
All right.
You're a sight for sore eyes.
You're looking good.
Jimmy.
Sorry you had to come
all this way.
It's a long way, right?
It's a long way.
Yeah. Sorry.
Only two things I know
about Albuquerque:
Bugs Bunny should've taken
a left turn there,
and give me a hundred tries,
I'll never be able to spell it.
[CHUCKLES]
Anyway...
Uh, as you can see,
I'm in a-- A bit of a pickle.
You certainly are.
[CHUCKLES]
Forget the property damage
and assault charges.
You face being labeled
a sex offender, Jimmy.
If that happens,
it'll follow you
for the rest of your life.
That is insane.
Okay?
That is a trumped-up load
of horse crap, Chuck. Come on.
Is that what I tell the judge?
"Load of horse crap"?
I'm not the lawyer here.
It was a Chicago sunroof.
Sex offender?
That's not even remotely a...
[CHUCKLES]
[SCOFFS]
Let's talk strategy, okay?
Because I need you
to work your magic
and make this whole situation
go "poof."
You got a plan
of attack? Huh?
Come on, I know I haven't
made it easy for you,
but you are--
You are the man.
Right? I know you've got
a million legal loopholes
that we can dance through,
big bag of tricks.
You know, any clever
technicalities, huh?
Reasonable-doubt-type stuff?
Come on, Chuck.
I haven't seen you in,
what, five years?
We barely hear from you.
Now that you're in it
up to your neck,
you can't even call me yourself.
You have Mom call me?
Mom took it
upon herself to call.
I was letting her know
where I was.
You didn't cry to her
on the phone?
What? No.
You didn't cry
and beg Mom for help?
Wha--? Jesus. She hears
what she wants to hear, okay?
I'm gonna cry on a payphone
in the middle of
Cook County Jail. Jesus.
Can we--? Can we talk
strategy here, huh?
Look--
I know I'm a lousy brother.
I'm a lousy brother,
I'm a big screw-up.
And if I was
just a better person,
I would not only stop
letting you down--
You know what?
I'd stop letting me down.
And it's about time
that I started to make
both of us proud.
Am I right?
Guard.
Wait. Chuck,
wait, wait, wait.
No, no,
you can't leave me, no.
If I don't get out of this,
my life is over.
So long as
you understand that.
Yeah.
Jimmy, if I do this-- If.
--do not make a fool out of me.
I promise I won't.
Everything you're doing,
everything you're
involved with, that's over.
Just tell me what to do.
Whatever it is, I'll do it.
Just say it.
Please, Chuck?
Help me.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[SIGHING]
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
[LINE RINGS]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
JIMMY [OVER PHONE]:
Hey, it's me.
[GRUNTS]
Unh. Jimmy?
What's, uh...?
Jesus, what time is it?
Clock says 2,
but I think that might be
Ho Chi Minh's time zone.
What? What's happening?
Is Chuck all right?
Yeah, Chuck...
Chuck is Chuck. All right?
Everything's all right. Ahem.
I just wanted to call you.
So, uh...
Hey. What you doing?
Jimmy...
No. I'm not
talking dirty to you.
What? You think
that's the only reason
I would call you
at this time of night?
I mean, can we just--?
Give me a little bit
of credit, okay?
And you're not talking dirty
to me either.
Okay, bye.
I knew it.
Joking.
Just joking,
having fun with you.
I am calling you tonight with
quality, PG phone conversation.
PG-13 at worst.
Uh-huh.
Hand to God. You know?
But, uh, if you hang up now
and drive straight over,
limited time only, I'm offering
a free pedicure and foot bath.
Is that right? Wow.
Maybe next time.
Hey. More for me. Ahem.
Uh, you're, uh, probably
swamped with work anyways,
what with that big,
fat giant case
falling right into your lap.
Which case is that?
I don't know. Some, uh...
Some county official
or something?
It was in all the papers.
Craig Kettleman.
Yeah. The primo client
your dipwad boss stole
right out from under me.
Nobody stole anybody.
The Kettlemans made a choice.
So did the Donner party,
when they took that shortcut.
Come on.
Hamlin is not that bad.
And I'm gonna be second chair
if it ever goes to trial, so...
be happy for me.
Hey, uh, how much exactly
did Kettleman get away with?
Mm, excuse me.
Innocent until proven guilty.
Uh, excuse me, but I'm
a taxpayer in this county.
I think I have a right to know.
And besides, it's not like
I'm his lawyer or anything.
I have to go to sleep.
So do you. I know
you have court in the morning.
He got away with a million,
million six, at least?
I'm not talking details
of a case with you. Good night.
Where did he stash
all that dough?
Besides for buying
that idiotic boat.
Hello? Guilty.
Hanging up now.
This guy is...
You know,
he's probably a target.
Somebody might get
some bad, bad ideas.
You know, if Kettleman isn't
careful with that money,
I mean, his whole family
could be in danger.
What do you mean, danger?
Jimmy, why would you say that?
What?
You said the family
might be in danger.
I did? I...
I... Ahem.
I'm-- I'm drunk. Heh.
So I'm just, uh...
I'm thinking out loud.
I'm not spinning, uh...
I'm spinning thoughts.
You sure?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Uh...
So I will see you down
in the court bowels mañana.
Good night, Kim.
Good night, Jimmy.
I'm no hero.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[CAR DOOR BEEPING]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGS]
KETTLEMANS [ON RECORDING]:
Hello! You've reached
Team Kettleman!
CRAIG:
Leave a message for Craig--
BETSY: Betsy--
WARREN: Warren--
JO JO: And Jo Jo--
ALL: --after the beep!
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGS]
KETTLEMANS [ON RECORDING]:
Hello! You've reached
Team Kettleman!
CRAIG:
Please leave a mess--
[COINS CLATTERING]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGS]
CRAIG [OVER PHONE]:
Hello?
[MUFFLED]
Kettlemans, you're in danger.
You're in danger.
I'm sorry, what?
Craig, who is it?
I'm not sure.
Wait, say--?
Say that again, please?
[OVER SPEAKER]
They know about your money.
Watch out.
Yeah, what are you
trying to say?
This is a warning.
You're in danger.
They're coming
for your money.
This is a friendly stranger.
Your whole family is in danger.
The money.
They know about the money.
You have a terrible
connection.
I'm warning you.
They know about your money.
Be careful.
Can you call back
on a better line?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Kettlemans, you're in danger.
They're coming for your money.
Bye.
CRAIG:
What did he say?
We're--
In danger.
"They're coming."
Who--?
Who's coming?
[♪♪♪]
Okay, how about this?
Time served plus counseling.
MAN: Can't do it.
It's his first offense.
"Can't do it, can't do it."
Would you work with me here?
I'm listening, aren't I?
Well, you're kind of
a captive audience.
What'd you eat for lunch,
the whole roast beast?
Funny.
Okay. Okay.
Hear me out.
Wow.
The 30 he's done,
which is a 60 credit,
plus 60 additional days.
Can't do it.
Best offer.
Six months plus
the time he's done,
halftime for good behavior,
out in 90, that's my final.
That's never gonna happen.
Oh!
Come on.
Now, are you joking?
Now, that is the best deal
you're gonna get.
I can't do it.
The guy drove drunk
into a shopping center
and killed three people.
Shopping center?
Desmond Rojas.
Armed robbery,
liquor store.
He assaulted a cashier
with a bottle of Kahlúa.
Oh, I was thinking
Darryl Redwood.
Yeah, okay, my bad.
Desmond Rojas.
Okay, go. Start over.
I am not starting over.
I'm busting my nut here
for 700 a throw,
inhaling your B.M.
straight from Satan's bunghole,
and you can't tell
one defendant from another?
Ninety days with good behavior.
We're doing this.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Say it. Say the words
"I accept the deal."
Yeah, I accept--
I accept the deal.
[SCOFFS]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Good morning.
What do you mean,
what did I mean?
No, I told you,
I was drunk. I just--
Kim, why are you
asking me this?
Oh, damn it. Here.
I'm in a real rush.
I didn't have time
to get the validation.
Fine. Nine bucks.
I-- I don't have it.
I have 5. Please?
You know the drill,
money or the validation.
Look, this is
an emergency, okay?
A serious, serious emergency.
I have to get out of here.
I promise, on the souls
of my forefathers,
I will get you the stickers
when I come back.
I will get you extra
if you just let me go.
Fine. Fine. You're gonna
make me walk back
and get the stickers,
I will walk back
and get the stickers.
I'm not making you do anything.
Those are the rules.
Hey, whatever helps you
sleep at night.
Screw you, geezer!
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
Oh, no, just want to make sure
we check that back door.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
MAN 2:
Copy that, dispatch.
MAN 3:
Okay, gentlemen, we're searching
in a two block radius.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Jimmy.
What brought you here?
Me? Uh, I was surfing
the police scanner.
Heard there was
big activity out this way.
There's no business
for you.
Maybe next time.
Uh, it was a home invasion?
Uh, the Kettlemans okay?
We don't know.
Neighbor was
walking the dog last night,
saw the front door wide open.
Place is ransacked,
no sign of the family.
There's no note,
so we're still figuring it out.
I gotta get back.
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
Good luck.
Why did you come here?
I'm supporting a friend in need.
You wanna be supportive?
Tell me why you said
those things.
I'm reading tea leaves.
Same way I knew
the Kettlemans needed a lawyer.
All that money.
It's logical somebody
would come after it.
So the same night you worry
about them, they disappear?
Yeah, it's crazy.
It's Ripley's.
Jimmy. It's not just
Craig and Betsy Kettleman.
It's their two kids as well.
You would say something if you
could help find them, right?
I--I don't know
what happened to them.
Really, I don't know.
[♪♪♪]
The longer you stay, the more
explaining I have to do.
I'll talk to you later.
Hey...
You'll tell me
if there's anything I can do?
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
Everything is gonna be fine.
It's gonna work out.
A-okay.
It's gonna be fine.
[COINS CLATTER]
[LINE RINGS]
NACHO [ON RECORDING]:
Nacho. Leave it.
Uh... Yes, I'm, uh--
Ahem. This is the party
you spoke to the other day,
uh, and I sincerely
want to help you
de-escalate
your situation legally
and otherwise.
Um, so call me at 146-8729
at your earliest convenience.
But soon. Please.
[SIGHS]
[COINS CLATTERING]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGS]
NACHO [ON RECORDING]:
Nacho. Leave it.
Yeah, Nacho. Hi. Uh...
Just to clarify. Look,
I don't know anything. Uh...
I have spoken to no one,
and there are no rats
on this ship.
But for the sake
of everyone involved,
I would just like
to open a dialogue.
So 146-8729.
Call me when you get this.
[COINS CLATTER]
If I didn't say it before,
time is of the essence
on this matter.
So, uh, I'm gonna hang up now
if you're trying to call.
Uh, there's no call waiting here
if you get a busy signal.
146-8729. Just keep trying.
I'll be here.
I can put out this fire,
if there is a fire.
By hope of hopes, this is
all a big misunderstanding.
146-8729.
[RINGS]
Hello?
Nacho? Nacho.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Walking. Just walking.
Strolling along.
[♪♪♪]
[SIREN WAILS]
Oh, thank God. Help. Help.
Down.
Show us your hands.
You guys are cops?
I've got bad knees!
Ow! Oh. Unh, unh.
Officers,
you're making a mistake.
My name's McGill,
James McGill.
I'm an attorney.
Easy. Easy.
It's his lawyer.
Whose lawyer?
You sure he asked for me?
Going in or what?
Hey. Ahem.
You asked for me,
and I have come.
I want to tell you,
this was a wise move.
Very smart,
because I'm here to help.
Everyone, all parties,
but mostly you.
Uh, those two detectives,
they just gave me an earful,
and what they were
telling me is...
It's problematic.
I'm gonna
pitch it back to you,
so I know
we're on the same page.
A neighbor lady
saw a suspicious van
parked across the street
from the Kettlemans' house
two nights in a row.
She wrote down
the license plate.
It was your license plate.
Cops tracked your van
and you,
searched it
and found blood
on the floor.
So here we are.
Um... Um...
They're calling the FBI
in on this,
which makes it federal.
That's a bad thing, Nacho.
That's very bad.
But if you tell me
where the family is,
if you give them up now,
full cooperation,
deep remorse,
I feel very good
about knocking your sentence
down to the minimum,
18 years.
They take this good behavior
thing very seriously,
so start here,
right here.
[SIGHS]
Tell me
the family is okay.
the kids are okay.
You wanna tell me
your thoughts and weigh in?
Does this sound like a plan
that you can get behind?
You miserable piece of shit.
You set me up.
I what?
You gave my score
to another crew,
and now you're
setting me up.
What the--? What?
Did the cops beat you?
You're talking like a person
with head trauma.
You think you're funny?
What are you saying?
You're saying you had
nothing to do with this?
That was your van
outside the house.
You weren't there?
Yeah, I was there.
I was casing the place.
Figuring out the best way
in and out,
what time they went to bed,
all that.
They were fine when I left.
That's it.
You had nothing to do
with the Kettlemans?
I was never in the house.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
What about the blood
in your van?
They DNA my ride,
all they're gonna find
is the blood
of your skate rat twins,
plus whatever
piss and shit
you leaked out
when you were in there.
Nobody's been
in the back of that van since.
I don't understand.
Here's what I understand,
counselor.
I told my plan
to one other person.
One.
You.
Now here I am
under arrest.
Go figure.
I don't know anything about
a setup or another crew. Heh.
You know what?
I don't even care.
The cops are out there
right now
poking into my business,
and if they find something
on me or my partners, for real,
it's gonna be bad for you.
Really bad.
Bad?
Bad as in...?
You get me out of here today,
or you're a dead man.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Oh, hey.
I asked
if you knew anything.
You didn't tell me you were
representing the lead suspect.
I didn't know at the time.
DUNST: He give up anything?
What?
Did he tell you
where the family is?
He doesn't know.
What does that mean?
He gave them to somebody?
He doesn't know
because he didn't do it.
Give me a break.
Guys, can you give us
just a minute?
Jimmy, that family
is in real danger.
You don't have to stand behind
attorney/client privilege.
I'm not.
These people can be
buried in a box
sucking air
through a straw.
I'm sorry if that's
where they are.
But my guy didn't do it.
How are you so sure?
You know what you're gonna do?
You're gonna get
your special CSI people
and test the blood
from that van.
I guarantee you
one billion percent
it's not the Kettlemans'.
Whose is it?
It's not the Kettlemans'.
Just test it.
That'll take weeks,
if we can even get
a sample to compare it to.
Well, isn't that convenient?
You've got an innocent man
in there right now
who I demand you release
with an apology.
There are no other suspects.
There's no evidence
that points to anyone else.
I wanna see the crime scene.
You guys are missing something.
RUSSO:
Screw you, "missing something."
No, detectives, I, um...
I think that's a good idea.
A good idea?
KIM: Yes.
We should invite Mr. McGill
to the house.
Why?
Yeah, why?
RUSSO:
So, what'd we miss?
This is the son's room,
Warren.
Twelve years old.
Jo Jo's room.
KIM:
She's 7.
All right,
you wanted me to crack,
mission accomplished.
But I'm telling you,
my client didn't do this.
Varga was outside the night
the family disappeared.
That is a fact.
Advocate for the guy
all you want
after we get these people
back safe.
In the meantime, help us.
Where's the doll?
Where's the what?
Uh, got little shoes,
bunch of clothes,
table and chairs, hairbrush,
but where's the doll
that goes with this?
In every picture of this girl,
she's holding the same doll.
So where's the doll?
What does it matter?
Doll is gone, girl is gone,
which means doll and girl
are most likely together,
which means--
I have no idea.
JIMMY:
Which means the kid wasn't
dragged out of the house,
ipso facto.
Wait.
What are you saying?
Maybe the Kettlemans
kidnapped themselves.
That's it.
You're done.
Let's go.
It makes perfect sense.
How? Why would they do that?
They stole
million dollars plus, right?
You wanna get away with
that cash, what do you do?
Run?
No, you can't.
If you run, everyone knows
you're guilty.
Ah. But if you're kidnapped,
you're a victim. Right?
They staged this
to throw everyone off.
You guys are looking
in the wrong place.
Who knows how many miles into
Mexico or Canada they could be?
You gotta put the word out.
Oh, come on, you don't think
it's possible I'm right?
It's possible.
Unlikely.
JIMMY: Unlikely?
All their cars are here.
There's no record of a taxi
or car service to the house.
They didn't get on any planes
or buses or trains.
You checked all that?
Yes. The doll, it's not news.
We saw it was missing.
So where is it?
The girl was scared,
crying.
Bad guy lets the kid
take the doll to shut her up.
What? You don't think
that's possible?
I need to talk to you,
alone.
I've gotta tell you something,
and promise not to be upset.
No way am I making that promise.
I called the Kettlemans.
After I hung up with you,
I gave them a warning call.
A warning call?
I was worried my guy Varga
was going after their money,
and he was.
He was gonna rip them off.
I deduced it
from a conversation we had.
It was lawyer-to-client,
so there was,
you know,
confidentiality issues.
But I called the Kettlemans
anonymously to warn them.
Anonymously? You did--?
Oh, God, you didn't--?
You didn't do
the sex robot voice, did you?
I did, the tube
and the whole thing,
which probably scared
the living shit out of them,
and they took off.
Which, you know,
file that under
unintended consequences,
but you believe me now?
Uh--
Great.
Now we have to find them.
Or better yet,
get the cops to let Varga go,
because right now my ass is on
the highway to the danger zone.
Why are you in danger?
Nacho Varga,
he didn't kidnap the family,
but he's a bad guy.
He's a very bad guy,
and if the cops
keep pushing him
they're gonna find something,
and when that happens,
Nacho blames me,
and then his guys...
turn me
into a meat piñata.
Jimmy, tell the police.
There's no way
I'm gonna rat on this guy.
I will never be safe.
I have to convince
the cops I'm right,
get them to stop
looking at Nacho
and catch the Kettlemans
on the run.
And if they never
catch them?
The Kettlemans?
You've met these people, right?
They're not
exactly masterminds.
They will be caught
if the cops are looking.
So you tell them to,
would you?
The FBI too. I heard
they're getting in on this.
Why would the FBI listen to me?
Hamlin. They'll listen to him.
APD, at least.
You talk to Howard,
you explain things to him.
He has clout
with these people.
What, is that a no, or...?
Hamlin will never agree to it.
The Kettlemans are our clients.
This would mean
incriminating them.
You see? This is why
people hate lawyers.
It's Hamlin's call,
and Hamlin will never agree.
And even if it were up to me,
you know I couldn't.
I'm sorry, I just--
I get it.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go talk to Nacho,
try to make him
see reason.
To beg.
Come on.
Right. Yeah, hey. Ahem.
I was a jerk, okay?
So I will pay you
what I owe you plus interest
if you just
let me come through.
I suggest you find parking
somewhere else.
Somewhere else,
as in where, somewhere else?
Not my concern.
Actually, this is your job,
so by definition
it's your concern.
So pump out the ticket and open
the stupid gate already, please.
I mean, I don't have time
for this.
[HORN HONKS]
[SCOFFS]
All--
All right.
[HORN HONKS]
Great.
I'm gonna park right here.
I don't think
you wanna be doing that.
JIMMY:
Oh, yeah?
What are you gonna do, you got
a poop-filled diaper in there?
You gonna throw it at me?
Are you gonna gum me to death,
huh, geezer?
Oh! Aah! Ow! Ow!
[GROANING]
Ow! Ow!
We're talking about a family.
Mom, dad, two kids.
Lawyer's got
this bullshit theory
about them staging this,
running off with the money.
Know the story?
Yeah. County treasurer
embezzled funds.
I read the paper.
We got this gangbanger
dead to rights.
Only problem
is your guy over there.
He needs to help us get
his scumbag client to talk.
So, what do you say?
You onboard?
Help us do some good.
Sure.
Okay, you assaulted this man.
Give me a break.
I barely touched the guy.
You laid hands on him first.
Finger. I laid finger on him.
RUSSO:
Whatever your interpretation,
it was still assault.
DUNST:
This gentleman is
willing to let this go,
not press charges,
if you help us out.
Get your client to tell us
where he has the family stashed.
Guys, I'm the definition
of a broken record on this.
Nacho is nacho man,
comprendo?
Nobody took the Kettlemans.
The Kettlemans took themselves.
You gonna keep
playing that line,
it's gonna go rough.
You know what?
Do your worst.
All right, let's go. To booking.
Yeah. Sure. Fine.
Perfect end to a perfect day.
Wait a second.
I changed my mind.
I'm sorry, what?
I don't wanna press charges.
We talked about this.
You wanna press charges.
No. No, I don't.
What are you doing, buddy?
I thought you had our backs.
No, I don't think
I said that, buddy.
RUSSO:
What, you get a chance to do
the right thing and puss out?
Mm... Yeah.
Well, I guess it's my loss.
Hey, Cagney, Lacey,
when you realize how wrong
you are about all this,
I'll take an edible arrangement
as a sorry,
heavy on the pineapple.
[SIGHS]
JIMMY:
Hey. Hold up. How come you
let me off the hook back there?
I'm going back to work.
Why don't you quit
while you're ahead?
I refuse to believe
it's because
you have something resembling
a heart inside your body.
You're not gonna have
a heart inside your body
in about five seconds.
Don't tell me, all right?
I already know
why you did it.
Yeah? Why's that?
Because you believe me.
That family kidnapped
themselves.
[CHUCKLES]
All right,
I believe you.
I knew it. I knew it.
Finally, someone believes me.
[LAUGHS]
Why do you believe me?
I heard the details.
Your story makes sense.
Of course it does.
Devil's advocate,
like the cop said,
the Kettlemans' cars
are still at their house.
No record of them leaving.
How'd they
get out of the country?
They didn't.
Odds are they didn't
get out of the neighborhood.
Come again?
Look,
when I was still on the job
back in Philly,
we had this case.
Hold up, hold up.
Now, wait.
"On the job," as in,
you were a cop on the job?
This bookie disappeared
after the Super Bowl.
Cowboys-Steelers.
Took $6 million in bets
and skipped town
when things didn't go his way.
Everybody thought he was
on the beach in the Bahamas,
or dead in the Jersey Pine
Barrens. Wasn't the case.
He was two doors down
from where he lived
in a foreclosed house.
Hid there for six months
without anyone suspecting him.
But why? Why not run?
That's what everybody expects.
It's human nature
to want to stay close to home.
And if this Kettleman
figured out how to do it,
that's what he did.
Nobody wants to leave home.
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
[♪♪♪]
♪ Baby, you know me well ♪
♪ You know I mean what I say ♪
♪ Before I say farewell ♪
♪ I'll give you one more day
So you can ♪
♪ Find out what's happening ♪
♪ Find out what's happening
Before long ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ If you don't
Find out what's happening ♪
♪ You're gonna find out
That I'm gone ♪
♪ Gone, gone, gone, gone ♪
♪ Tell me
What you're gonna do ♪
♪ You better
Make up your mind ♪
♪ It all depends on you ♪
♪ Oh, I'm leaving you behind ♪
♪ You'd better
Find out what's happening ♪
♪ Find out what's happening
Before long ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ If you don't
Find out what's happening ♪
♪ You're gonna find out
That I'm gone ♪
♪ Gone, gone, gone, gone ♪
♪ Baby, you know it's true ♪
♪ We've been through
Thick and thin ♪
♪ But if you don't
Come through ♪
♪ You won't ever
See me again ♪
♪ You'd better
Find out what's happening ♪
♪ Find out what's happening
Before long ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ If you don't
Find out what's happening ♪
♪ You're gonna find
Your daddy gone ♪
♪ Gone, gone, gone, gone ♪
♪ Find out what's happening ♪
♪ Find out what's happening ♪♪
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
WOMAN:
Okay? Let's do this. And...
KETTLEMANS:
♪ There was a farmer had a dog
And Bingo was his name-o ♪
♪ B-I-N-G-O ♪
♪ And Bingo was his name-o ♪
♪ There was a farmer had a dog
And Bingo was his name-o ♪
[HANDS CLAP]
♪ I-N-G-O ♪
♪ And Bingo was his name-o ♪
♪ There was a farmer had a dog
And Bingo was his name-o ♪
[HANDS CLAP]
♪ N-G-O ♪
Hey, it's me. Listen to this.
♪ N-G-O
And Bingo was his name-o... ♪
You hear that?
I found your dumb-ass clients.
[HANDS CLAP]
♪ G-O ♪
[STAMMERING]
It's a long story.
Look, I'm taking them
back to their place.
We'll meet you there.
Give me a couple hours.
[HANDS CLAP]
♪ O ♪
♪ O
And Bingo was his name-o ♪♪
Yay.
That was great, guys.
Yeah. I think we have time
for one more before bed.
Do we have to?
Oh, hey, I don't know about you,
but I would love a little
"John Jacob Jingleheimer
Schmidt."
You know what?
Let's really have fun
with this one, okay,
Kettle-team?
Let's do this. And...
Here's Johnny!
[ALL SCREAMING]
Hey. Hey, Warren. Hey, Jo Jo.
Uh, sorry about that.
I'm your uncle Jimmy,
all right?
Now, your parents are gonna
take you down the mountain
back to your house.
That sound good?
Uh, we...
Yeah. See? They're excited.
Mr. McGill,
can we talk about this?
No, we can't. Okay?
You're done here.
Pack up your stuff
because we're heading back.
Civilization awaits.
Finally.
[FINGERS SNAP]
Look, please, can we
just talk this through?
Not an option. You do this
on your own recognizance,
or the cops
drag you by your heels.
Let's go. Kettlemans,
BETSY: No. No.
time to ship out.
Yes, you are. This is happening.
No. No, this is not happening!
JIMMY:
Yes, Kettlemans.
No!
Yes, you are doing this now.
Let go! No!
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]