JIMMY:
Works every--
I'm telling you, every time.
Do it, try it.
No. What, right now?
Right here.
All right, all right.
[HOWLS WEAKLY]
Kind of. Kind of that.
Gotta work on it, bro.
All right, man.
Seriously.
All right, bro,
I'll work on it.
But just tell me,
when do you--?
Right before the cork pops.
Timing's important, but--
But you don't do it,
like, in her ear?
No, you don't do it
in her ear.
It's a given
you don't do it in her ear.
This is scientifically proven.
Really?
Prehistoric stuff. The medulla.
Ha, ha. Crazy, man.
The wolf brain.
The what?
It's primitive stuff.
Okay, let me try it again.
[HOWLING]
STEVIE: Yeah!
JIMMY: Ha-ha-ha.
STEVIE: That's the wolf brain!
JIMMY: Nice. Ha-ha-ha.
STEVIE:
Ha. Man, this town sucks.
Sorry, bro, I know
it's yours and everything,
but it's not even 2.
JIMMY:
Yeah, it does kind of suck.
Hey, I know this
after-hours place over--
A couple blocks off Cermak.
You wanna hit it?
Hells, yeah. Let's do it.
Fuckin' hit it.
[STEVIE LAUGHS]
JIMMY:
That's what I'm talking about.
STEVIE:
Whoo!
[STEVIE HOWLS]
JIMMY:
Okay.
[BOTH HOWLING]
[BOTH LAUGH]
Not in her ear, right?
Right, not in her ear.
Hey, bro, I never did
catch your name.
Saul.
Saul?
"S'all good, man."
Ha!
Get it?
I do. All right, Saul.
Hey, hey, brother, whoa.
Check it out. What is that?
Holy shit.
There's gotta be at least
a thousand bucks in here.
Oh, my God, look at that.
Whose is it?
Mine.
Hey, possession's
like four-tenths
of the what-do-you-call-it,
bro.
Like, is there an ID or...?
Yeah.
I don't know, some fat guy.
Huh.
I'm thinking that one.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Let's see.
Jesus.
Is he, uh...?
What?
I don't know.
Ah!
Hey.
Hey, fella. You all right?
[HUMMING
"SMOKE ON THE WATER"]
Hey, buddy.
Hey, would you answer me?
Hey, answer this, you butthole.
"Butthole"? What the hell?
Hey, uh--
Hey, bro,
be nice, all right?
This guy right here,
he's trying to help you.
Help yourself to some of this,
you butthole.
STEVIE: Hey.
JIMMY: Hey, we're not buttholes.
All right? So stop saying that.
STEVIE: Yeah.
♪ Butt, butt, butthole ♪
JIMMY:
Hey, man, what's your problem?
My problem is I'm standing here
talking to a couple buttholes.
Actually, you're not standing,
you fat bastard.
You're laying
on your fat ass.
Hey, I'll roundhouse-kick you
right in your heads.
You think I won't?
I'll come into the McDonald's
where you work,
I'll buy the whole damn place
and I'll fire you.
I'll say, "Drop your mops,
you buttholes,
because you're fired."
And then
I'll roundhouse-kick you
right in your stupid heads.
And then I'll go
Jean-Claude Van Damme
on you, you...
[SNORING]
Butthole.
I'm keeping the money.
Heh, heh.
Here you go, fatty.
I got dibs
on that watch, man.
I didn't see that.
What kind is it?
I don't know,
it's just a watch.
We gotta get out of here, man.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What kind of watch is it?
It's-- I don't know, it's--
Well, then let me look at it.
It's a damn Rolex.
I-- I don't know.
Not cool to be greedy, bro.
Not cool.
I didn't know what--
So how do you wanna
split this up?
Tell you what.
You keep the cash.
I'll just keep the watch.
It's worth 3 grand.
What?
Three thousand, easy.
No.
Yeah.
Hey, hey, hey. Come on, now.
Let's figure this out.
Gotta get out of here.
All right, you're right.
You know what?
I will sweeten the pot.
You got 5, 20, 40, 60, 80--
Five hundred and eighty bucks.
Add that to the thousand,
it's more than half.
What do you know
about that thing?
Is it worth more than 3?
No, I don't know,
but we're good, right?
Yeah, we good? Okay?
I don't know.
Later, sucker!
[LAUGHING]
[STEVIE HOWLS]
[UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN:
Six left.
Can we get more?
God, I hope so.
It's like a license
to print money.
Heh. Thing of beauty.
Hey, what was that crazy stuff
about roundhouse kicks?
Where did you get that?
I don't know.
Just something in my brain,
you know? It just came out.
Too much?
No, I loved it.
It was, like,
deep or something.
Wanna talk about
brilliant, I mean...
You're the man.
Me, I'm just...
I love
watching you work, man.
It's good for making beer money.
That's about all.
♪ You can smile ♪
♪ That's all right
My friend ♪
[♪♪♪]
BETSY:
Please, no one has to know.
You could just pretend
you didn't find us.
We would never tell anyone,
would we, Craig?
CRAIG: No, absolutely not.
BETSY: No.
I already called
your lawyer.
Besides, this little
family outing of yours
has put an innocent man
in jail.
The cops are investigating this
as a kidnapping.
They already rounded up
some poor suspect.
A working-class guy.
A father, I think.
But anyway, you two, you almost
ruined someone's life.
Potentially several someones.
We had no idea.
Could this have been
the person in the van?
What if the man they arrested
is the one we were warned about?
Yeah, maybe he's not
so innocent. Hm?
Warned? Warned how?
BETSY:
We had a phone call.
Someone disguising their voice.
They said someone
was coming for us.
And there was a van
outside the house,
as if whoever was inside
was watching us.
Mm-hm.
And once that drove off,
we did what we did.
For the kids.
The kids.
I wouldn't know
about any of that, I just--
Ahem. I can assure you that
you and your family are safe.
The police are all over
this thing, so...
BETSY:
It doesn't matter.
We can't just go back.
Our case.
They'll crucify Craig.
Can't you just call
Ms. Wexler again?
Tell her you didn't
see us after all.
If they think I ran away,
it'll look like
I did something wrong.
Yeah, and we can't risk
losing everything
just because
of some teensy mistake.
Can I ask you something?
What were you hoping
would happen?
I mean, before I found you,
what were you planning to do?
Well, we were in the process
of, you know,
working that out,
when you, um...
We were working that out,
yeah.
All right, well,
you've still got
a little bit of maneuverability,
all right?
You're outdoorsy, right?
So you went on
an impromptu camping trip.
I don't know, it's something
people do, apparently. Uh...
You left the house a mess,
and you kicked in
your own front door
because it's a free country.
Kim Wexler is very good.
She'll make it work.
What about the money?
If she knows about it,
she'll tell. Right?
I mean,
she'll have to tell.
Well, like they say
in Silicon Valley,
"It's not a bug,
it's a feature."
You ever hear of
a bargaining chip?
What we have
right here
is the mother
of all bargaining chips.
As in...
you expect us
to give this back?
We are not
giving this back.
We are not guilty.
This money belongs to us.
We-- Well, I mean,
Craig earned it.
I worked very hard.
Yeah.
Weekends, holidays, all unpaid.
All unpaid.
Always. And really,
just because you're salary
doesn't mean
you don't deserve overtime.
I think
that's only fair.
Really, that's what
this is about, right?
Fairness.
Fairness, right.
I mean,
not just what's legal.
You wanna talk about legal,
slavery, that used to be legal.
Human slavery.
So...
Yeah, this is right up there
with that.
Please, just don't tell
anyone about the money.
I can't take a bribe.
Who would know?
We won't tell anyone.
Yeah, take it.
I can't take it.
Please, didn't you say
that you wanted to help us?
Just pretend you never saw
the money. How hard is that?
Take it.
I can't--
I can't take a bribe.
[CLEARS THROAT]
But you know what I ca--?
I can take a retainer.
A retainer?
Yeah, for my services...
as your lawyer.
You're not our lawyer.
Well, not yet.
Look, I know that HHM
is shiny and it's slick
and it's chock-full of lawyers,
and compared to them I'm like
a kiddie lemonade stand
trying to compete with Walmart,
but here's the thing:
What are you gonna get from me
that you're not gonna get
from those other guys?
Passion. Commitment.
Ask yourself this:
Who found you?
I don't see Howard Hamlin
ruining his $300
Gucci loafers out here.
If you're with me,
you're my number one client.
Morning, noon or night,
you call me, I'm there.
I would be singularly
devoted to you.
Why not?
BETSY:
I'm sorry.
You're just...
Just what?
You're the kind of lawyer
guilty people hire.
[MACHINE BUZZES]
Did it make the paper?
What?
Did what make the paper?
Okay, well, probably
missed the deadline,
but check it out
tomorrow morning.
Front page. The Kettlemans,
all four of them,
safe and sound.
Looks like you called it.
Yeah.
Camping, you know?
Pretty much right
in their own backyard.
Well, ahem,
five miles above it. Jesus.
The night I had.
I got pine nuts in my shoes.
But, I mean,
can you believe it?
I guess you can.
It's just, you know,
you assume that criminals are
gonna be smarter than they are.
I don't know, it kind of
breaks my heart a little.
Not the loquacious sort,
are you?
We can't all be
as blessed as you.
Well, thanks for your help.
Don't mention it.
And, uh, if you ever need
any assistance...
[DOOR OPENS]
Whoa, whoa,
why is my client in handcuffs?
This man is innocent.
He's a victim.
Why on earth
would he be cuffed?
Go ahead, take them off.
There you go.
Free at last. Hey, did he
tell you the good news?
Never even kidnapped.
How about that?
A family can't go
on a little vacation
without the whole city
going on lockdown?
Where is your partner?
Did you lose the coin toss?
Because we expect an apology
from him as well as you.
You really don't wanna push
your luck with me, scumbag.
We got eyes on you, asshole.
One little slip.
Just one.
Yeah.
Well, you're both
very pretty, so...
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Well, ahem, I believe I did more
than what you asked of me,
so that would
make us square, yes?
Great.
You need a ride?
Camping?
You expect me
to believe that shit?
Yeah, I know.
The things people do, huh?
They decide to go camping
right after I run
my little offer by you?
Could be argued that all of life
is one great coincidence.
Somebody told those people
to, um, go camping.
Somebody warned them.
Ahem. They're very woodsy.
And between you and me,
they're pretty rash when
it comes to the decision-making.
They're not really
the plan-ahead types.
Yeah, I'd cut
the cute attitude
right about now
if I were you.
You ratted on me.
There will be consequences.
JIMMY:
Hey, if somebody
warned the Kettlemans,
it was probably somebody who
was worried about those kids.
You know how much trouble
you caused me?
You didn't need any help
getting caught.
Okay? The neighbor ID'd you.
You were sloppy.
Any trouble you might have,
that's on you.
[WHISPERING]
Not to mention the blood
in your van.
Here's a thought:
Ajax, Formula 409.
You have no idea
the tap dance I had
to give those cops
to get you out of here.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
You gave them probable cause
out the wazoo.
Now, whoever the somebody is
who may have
warned the Kettlemans,
[WHISPERING]
got them out of there
before you did anything
even more stupid.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
You should be thanking
this Good Samaritan
because whoever he is,
he did you a favor.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, I'm thinking hourly here.
There were
some special circumstances,
so our elite-tier pricing
would be $950 an hour.
Round off to 20 hours.
[CALCULATOR WHIRRING]
Nineteen thousand.
Plus 1000 for travel expenses.
Consulting fees, 1500.
And, uh, research.
Five for filing fees.
I ate on the road.
And storage fees.
Miscellaneous expenses.
[SIGHS]
Upon this rock,
I will build my church.
TAILOR:
Double-breasted or single, sir?
Single. And I want you to cut
the arm holes high, okay?
Of course.
And trim through the middle.
Trim.
Cloth?
Uh, oh--
Well, uh, wool.
JIMMY:
Yeah, uh...
Super 170 Tasmanian wool.
Beautiful choice, sir.
Thanks.
Uh, navy, all right? Uh...
Yeah.
Uh-huh. Oh, that's it.
Perfect. Pinstripe.
Shall we discuss shirts?
Okay, I'm gonna need
your finest sea-island cotton
with a white club collar
and French cuffs.
I have the very thing.
And I'm assuming
you want to see some ties.
Yeah, I was picturing something
in a light-blue knit.
Okay.
Oh, and could you make sure
those are real mother-of-pearl
buttons on the shirts, okay?
None of this fake plastic crap.
Of course.
I'll be right back.
Some coffee, David?
[EASY-LISTENING MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
TAILOR:
Ah, here we are.
Shall we?
Yeah, let's go.
Mm. Mm-hm. Yeah.
So, um, what do you think?
Strawberry Fields Forever?
Mm.
No, are you crazy?
Not even close.
Yes, it is, look.
No, no, it's way more
Sassafras Glow. Way more.
Use your eyes.
Strawberry Fields Forever.
Ladies, back me up. Hey.
Sassafras Glow, am I right?
MRS. NGUYEN: No.
Maybe Rhapsody in Blond,
but...
See, they agree with me.
Whatever happened to
"the customer is always right"?
Sassafras Glow.
Mix it up, all right?
You're wrong.
You see.
Big deal. I'll wash it out
in the morning. No biggie, jeez.
It's bleach.
It doesn't wash out.
What? It's permanent?
We'll Photoshop
the color, okay?
Change of plan, ladies.
I wanna go with a simple
curling iron job, okay?
Uh, give me, like, ringlets,
you know, on top.
Like Tony Curtis in Spartacus.
Yeah, like the bath scene
in Spartacus.
[NGUYEN SPEAKING
IN VIETNAMESE]
JIMMY:
Stop talking about it.
Make me beautiful already.
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
JIMMY [ON RECORDING]:
Hello.
You've reached the law offices
of James M. McGill, Esquire,
a lawyer you can trust.
Kindly leave your information
at the tone,
and Mr. McGill
will phone you promptly.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
Hey, uh...
It's me. Hi.
Anyway, The Thing is playing
downtown on Saturday.
Thought you might be up
for some Kurt Russell action.
I owe you one, so why don't we
just grab some dinner first,
my treat?
And...
Uh, you know, if not,
can you give me a call anyway?
I really wanna talk to you.
Okay, bye.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Come in.
HOWARD: Hey.
Hey. Hey.
How goes it?
Uh...
Tricky, for sure.
Craig and Betsy really put us
in a corner with the police,
not to mention the press.
But this
camping story of theirs,
they've been keeping it
consistent at least.
If it's okay with you,
I think I should try
to talk them
into hiring a PR firm.
Certainly for
the next couple of weeks.
Mm-hm.
So okay on the PR firm?
Do you have a minute?
Yeah, of course. What's up?
Take a ride with me.
KIM:
Uh, okay. Uh...
Where are we going?
Whoa.
Yeah.
Shit.
Yep.
That's-- I mean,
that's my suit, right?
Am I crazy here?
No, you're not crazy.
Look at the logo.
That's our logo. He's just
straight-up copying us.
I mean, what the hell
is he thinking with this?
Really, he's, you know,
a free spirit.
Oh. Yeah.
That's one way to put it.
You two are still friends,
right?
I wouldn't exactly--
You talk, though.
Not really.
Still, you're the one he called
when he found the Kettlemans'
camped halfway up the Sandias.
He was just looking out
for his own client, that's all.
This isn't the third degree,
Kim.
I really don't care
one way or the other. I just...
[SIGHS]
He's really forcing
my hand here.
[MASSAGE CHAIR HUMMING]
[DOWNTEMPO JAZZ MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
JIMMY: Hey.
KIM: Hey.
Am I interrupting?
JIMMY:
Not at all.
Perfect timing. Come on.
Sit. Have a massage,
free of charge.
Okay.
You gotta try the footbath too.
Oh, yeah. Ah.
Give the old dogs a rest.
Go for the deep-tissue setting--
Is that the small fist?
Use the-- It's three arrows.
I did. I pressed it.
Yeah. Now, you feel it?
Good.
[MASSAGE CHAIR HUMMING]
Ah. Now, relax, okay?
Okay.
You deserve a break today.
It's very nice.
Told you.
I get this free
every night.
Just one of the perks
of salon living.
The others being?
Free cucumber water, obviously.
Obviously.
Free mani-pedis?
Uh, deep-discount mani-pedis.
Ah.
The ladies still gotta eat.
Well, it's still a deal.
Yeah.
You're living like a king, then.
Mm-hm.
[SIGHS]
What's this?
Is this a cease and desist?
Yep.
How pissed was he?
His head didn't actually
explode, but pretty damn pissed.
Like "this won't end well
for you" pissed.
Yeah.
How about that?
Jimmy.
This is serious.
I know.
Do you?
I mean, what the hell
is with that billboard?
I know you have
a problem with Hamlin,
but I just don't get
your angle here.
Aren't you trying to build
your own law practice?
Instead, you're spending
God knows how much money
turning yourself
into a little Hamlin clone.
I mean, why are you
making this personal?
It's not personal.
It is so personal.
It is completely
and totally personal.
No, no, no. It's not. Nope.
Yes. Yes, it is. Ugh.
Stop trying to pretend.
I can advertise,
can't I?
What, do I have
to clear everything
past the great Howard?
You can advertise all you want.
That billboard
is not advertising.
That is
a declaration of war.
"Declaration of war."
It's right at Hamlin's exit.
You know he drives
by it every day.
It's business.
I'm building a brand.
You're ripping off
a brand.
There is nothing original
in that ad.
It certainly doesn't
represent Jimmy McGill.
Hey. All right, now,
he fired the first shot, okay?
Trying to keep me from using
my name? My own name, Kim?
I get that.
But this?
You're better than this.
I'm better than this?
Yes, you are.
I'm better than this? I'm bet--
Well, you're better
than that schmuck Hamlin.
Oh, come on, Jimmy.
You could work anywhere.
You could be somewhere
where they appreciate you.
Where they see
how valuable you are.
Where, I don't know,
maybe they care about you.
Forget it, okay?
If Hamlin wants to come
after me, he knows where I am.
I'll be ready. Guns blazing.
[SIGHS]
[MASSAGE CHAIR STOPS]
The cease and desist
is just the beginning.
The next step is an injunction.
You can't win this fight.
[MASSAGE CHAIR HUMMING]
[SIGHS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Your Honor,
I'm a humble solo practitioner
merely trying
to ply my trade
in an aggressive
and evolving marketplace.
As I've argued repeatedly,
this is trademark infringement.
Mr. McGill's new logo
is an absolute copy of ours.
I think it falls firmly
under fair use.
Fair use?
You're clearly profiting,
so fair use doesn't apply.
There are only
so many fonts out there.
Does Mr. Hamlin
outright own them all?
No. But we've been using
this particular font
for 12 years now.
And it, in concert with
our tri-rectangle graphic
and Hamlindigo blue,
constitutes
a trademark-brand identifier.
Whoa, back up.
"Hamlindigo blue"?
Yes. That is
our trademark name.
Holy crap, you seriously
named a color Hamlindigo?
That is...
Yikes.
"Yikes."
From the man dressed
exactly like me. Your Honor,
I feel like I'm in the mirror
routine with Groucho Marx.
Like we should be standing
waving our arms.
Really?
I don't see it.
In addition, the name McGill
appears in both logos,
which Mr. McGill is hoping
to further confuse
potential clients.
So I can't advertise
under my own name now?
I'm to be penalized
because I happen to share a name
with one of HHM's partners?
You can't take
my name from me.
The name is not
the problem here, Mr. McGill.
Uh, Mr. Hamlin certainly
seems to think so.
I mean, he wants me
to change my name,
because he claims
that, what,
it's some kind of threat
to his business?
Your Honor--
This is restraint of trade.
Okay, whatever happened
to the free market, huh?
No, Hamlin wants you to tell--
Okay, enough, Mr. McGill.
I've heard enough.
All right, yes, you are
within your rights
to advertise
using your own name.
However,
in my estimation,
the billboard clearly
and intentionally
duplicates elements of
the Hamlin Hamlin McGill logo.
You're actively copying
their established brand
for your own gain.
I don't see
any other explanation.
Your Honor--
Jimmy. Jimmy.
Wise up.
The billboard must come down
within 48 hours.
This is a classic
David-versus-Goliath story.
I mean, you got
your gigantic law firm
stomping all over
the little guy.
Yeah, but it's investigative
journalism at its best.
It's right up your alley.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, okay. Well, let me
give you my cell just in case.
Yeah. Thank you.
[SIGHING]
[♪♪♪]
Can I get the news desk,
please? I got a hot tip.
Wanna be the station
that brought down big law?
You could be like the reporters
that brought down big tobacco.
Look, I'm talking
Woodward and Bernstein here.
Hey, your exposé on predatory
ATM fees, that was-- Wow.
Well,
it's a miscarriage of justice.
And I think your viewers
would be very, very interested
and grateful to you
for exposing this injustice.
I wouldn't characterize this
as a community health risk,
but it's definitely
community interest.
No, yes, HHM is a pillar
of the community. Yes.
No, the war is
an important story as well.
That's why this action
is so egregious.
Sure. Okay.
Well, at least consider
the human-interest angle here.
Are you kidding? "Lawyer pulls
himself up by his bootstraps
only to be ground under the heel
of the old-money mega-firm"?
That's hearts and minds.
You--
Hell--
Yeah,
I have your number too, so...
Yeah, I see. Okay.
[♪♪♪]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
Oh, no, no, no, man.
Can't touch the goods.
I signed the form.
Only I can touch the camera.
Fine. May I suggest
you widen the frame to include--
The billboard
is the story, okay?
I'm also the story, so...
Gotta get me in there.
Okay, so get on your mark.
No offense to your minutes
of experience,
but I'd like to see what we got
before we do this, okay?
Other guy.
Only other guy that's here.
Go stand where I was standing.
Shrink down. Shrink down.
Yeah, scrunch. Yeah.
Okay, widen the frame,
get the billboard.
Okay, now get me.
Me, me, me.
No, not me.
Get him. He's me.
Yeah, like that.
Got it?
Yeah.
Good.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Okay.
Is he in the shot?
No. Dude, just go.
How do I look?
Great.
Well, uh...
No, this is my good side.
Heh.
[SIGHS]
Is the billboard in?
Yes. Jesus, just--
You said 100 for one hour,
not fricking three.
You clearly have
a journalistic impulse.
You're a go-getter.
You know that?
Go get this.
All right, count me down.
In five, four, three...
Gravitas.
I'm James McGill.
Like most Americans,
I'm a self-made man.
I put myself through law school.
Working in the courts
as a public defender,
I represented those
with nowhere else to turn.
I believe in service.
It's what I built my career on.
But I've also had a dream,
a dream that many of us have.
A dream to own my own business.
Well, I scrimped
and I saved,
and finally I was able
to buy one billboard.
A tiny foray
into advertising
for my fledgling law firm.
[SIGHS]
I've always been told
that America is
the land of opportunity,
and I believed it,
until today. Heh.
Not 24 hours
after my billboard went up,
a large law firm came after me.
They said that I was
hurting their business.
They're rich, they're powerful.
I'm just one man.
So who do you think
the court sided with?
So now my little billboard
comes down.
Let me tell you something.
If they want a fight,
they're gonna get a fight,
because I'm not giving up--
WORKER: Aah!
Holy shit. Dude, the dude!
Dude, the dude!
WORKER: Help!
The worker guy.
WORKER: Get me out of here!
Oh, shit.
Please. Get me down!
Dude.
Okay. Call 911.
WORKER:
Help me. Aah!
You got a cell?
Yeah, yeah.
WORKER: Please.
MAN: A guy fell off a billboard
from Frontage Road South
and Mountain.
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
Unh! Unh! Help me!
[WORKER GRUNTING]
I don't think
that's very safe!
You need to be
licensed for that!
WORKER: Help me.
Man.
JIMMY:
Not looking down.
One rung at a time.
[WORKER CONTINUES GRUNTING]
Hurry up!
Come get me.
Help!
[GRUNTING]
Help me.
Sir, I'm right here.
Please.
Pull me up.
Here.
Grab my hand.
Pull me up.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[BOTH PANTING]
You okay?
Took you long enough.
I was scared, yes. I mean,
I'm not really a big fan
of heights, let me tell you,
but, you know,
something inside me said:
"You have to do this."
I'm sure our city's
first responders
would have
been here momentarily...
Jesus, can you believe this guy?
This whole thing was a publicity
stunt. It's gotta be.
That's all anybody wants
when they're in trouble.
I didn't think life
was gonna call on me...
You don't think
anyone's gonna buy this?
...in an immediate,
life-threatening way.
It's hard to say.
People love a hero.
You take it
as it comes, right?
The universe put me
in that spot at that moment.
Who am I to say no?
You know, as a lawyer,
well, I help people every day.
Whole thing's a damn stunt.
I think my clients know
that when they're in trouble,
I'm there.
I'm just a guy
who was in the right--
[SIGHS]
[SIGHING]
[DIAL TONE DRONING]
[PHONE DIALING]
[LINE RINGING]
COMPUTERIZED VOICE:
You have seven new messages.
To listen to your messages,
press one.
First message.
Received at 5:40...
It's just showmanship,
Chuck. Ahem.
Yeah, right.
You're early.
Did you--?
Yeah, I grounded myself.
Hey, big day.
My phone's ringing
off the hook.
I have three consults
before lunchtime.
Three.
That's great, Jimmy.
Yep.
The worm has turned.
Oh, ha, ha.
That's really great.
So to what do you credit
this sudden change?
Well, I gotta admit,
you were right.
How so?
Well, you told me to keep
plugging and do good work
and the clients will come.
You know, I'll admit, I almost
lost faith a couple times.
But the worm has turned.
So, what, you've been getting
referrals from your PD clients?
Yeah. You know,
you work hard,
show you got half a brain
and people come knocking,
like you said.
I just needed
to get my face out there.
Oh. So the prosecutors then,
referring clients.
Yeah. Yep, exactly.
Was it Bergeron?
When I was starting out,
she sent me a couple
of good ones.
Yeah, uh, it was someone
on her team, you know.
I mean, hey, it just took some
elbow grease and clean living.
People noticed.
I knew you had it in you.
I don't see
the Journal here.
Oh. Here you go.
No.
Albuquerque Journal.
It's not here.
Oh, yeah.
I didn't see it outside.
It wasn't out there?
It's always out there.
I didn't see it. Heh.
Maybe they forgot to deliver it.
Maybe some kids grabbed it.
If there's one thing kids love,
it's local print journalism.
I don't know
what to tell you.
You got a ton
of reading material there.
Look, hey.
[WHISTLES]
Financial Times.
You know, I know Albuquerque
is a hub of global intrigue,
but you think
that'll tide you over?
Fine, but if it's not
here tomorrow,
I'll need you to call
the subscription office.
Yeah, will do. Look, I gotta go.
I don't wanna be late.
Hey, good luck today.
Thanks.
CHUCK:
Keep it up.
Hard work looks good on you.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CAR PULLS AWAY]
[♪♪♪]
[BLANKET RUSTLING]
[SIGHS]
[PANTS]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[HORN HONKING]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[♪♪♪]