[DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE]
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
COP 1: Albuquerque police.
Hello?
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
Sir, we'd like
to talk with you.
Could you
open the door, please?
We know you're in there.
You're casting a shadow
through your peephole.
All we wanna do is talk.
Would you please open the door?
I'd, uh...
I'd prefer not to, officers.
COP 2:
Sir, come on and open up.
I have a condition.
I can't go outside
or be exposed
to what's out there.
You were able to steal
your neighbor's newspaper.
I didn't steal it.
I left $5.
The cover price
is 50 cents.
COP 1:
Did your neighbor consent
to sell you her paper?
Uh-- She--
Isn't--?
Um...
Officer,
let's talk about
something called
"probable cause."
As I'm sure you know,
in New Mexico
there is a two-part test
to determine whether police
have an objectively
reasonable basis...
CHUCK:
--the situation as
Mincey v. Arizona pointed out,
create an event...
Hey, Tommy,
come around here, would you?
CHUCK:
And that's why the Tenth
Circuit Court of Appeals
ruled that a coercive order...
Check this out.
CHUCK:
--requiring an individual
to leave his house is seizure.
And therefore protected
under the Fourth Amendment.
Right?
COP 2:
Whole lot of camp stove fuel.
Guy sure sounds like a tweaker.
See what he did
to the breaker box?
Is he coming out,
or are we going in?
[♪♪♪]
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
COP 1:
You got ten seconds
to open this door
or it's coming down,
you hear me?
Ugh.
Final warning.
Okay, I'll let you in,
but you have to leave
your electronic devices outside.
No phones, no walkie-talkies,
no flashlights.
Definitely,
definitely no Tasers.
I can't emphasize that enough.
Deal?
Or-- Look, look,
I'll give the paper back.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
No--
[GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[BEEP]
RICKY [ON INTERCOM]:
Yeah?
James McGill
to see Mr. Richard Sypes.
Ricky.
Call me Ricky.
Come on in.
[SIGHS]
Uh, this is
my assistant's car. Heh.
My Mercedes is in the shop.
Yeah, I ought to give him
a raise. You're right.
RICKY:
Jim, I saw you on the TV.
That billboard thing?
And I had me
a pair of insights.
Insight the first:
You ain't afraid
to put yourself out there.
And insight the second:
You believe in the real America.
Freedom. Self-sufficiency.
I do. I--
I really do.
When I see a man like you
driving that foreign
shitbox of a car,
Well, see, actually--
it's a sign a good man
can't get ahead today.
It's a damn travesty,
that's what it is.
Well, that may be,
ahem, Ricky,
but, uh, I refuse
to consider myself a victim.
You know, we are once again
at a point in our history
where the fly-swatting hand
of government
is crushing the spirit
of entrepreneurship.
Taxes, OSHA requirements.
The INS poking
their big, fat nose
into every
mother-loving hire.
It's damned oppressive.
It's tragic.
It's un-American.
Jim, I think you are
just the lawyer I need,
because I got me a case.
Major.
I say, a major case.
Are you ready
to clear your calendar?
Ricky, I'm all ears.
I want to secede
from the United States.
Now, I got 1100 acres
of property here.
Self-sustaining
with solar power and wells.
A sovereign state
immune to the business-killing
regulations
of the country
in which it geographically lies.
We are going to be America's
Vatican City.
[SIGHS]
Ricky...
I'm your man.
Yeah. Let's do this.
Let's show 'em all.
Yee-haw!
Yee-haw! Ha, ha, ha.
Yes, we are doing this.
Now, it's not
gonna be easy, sir.
The government is gonna
fight us tooth and nail.
We could end up
in the Supreme Court.
I'm talking
thousands of man hours.
I mean, years of effort.
[SIGHS]
Are you ready for that?
Me?
I say bring 'em on.
Let's talk turkey.
What's your rate?
[OPERA MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Four hundred and fifty an hour.
To hell with hourly.
I want you on retainer.
How about one million even?
Five hundred up front
and 500 when we're done.
A million? Ahem. That seems...
fair.
Would you like that in cash?
Uh...
[SWALLOWS]
Tax-free and backed
by the full faith and credit
of the sovereign
Sandia Republic.
It's, uh...
Son...
you are getting in
on the ground floor.
Heh, heh, heh.
[CHUCKLES]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Mr. McGill, hi.
Thanks so much for coming.
Roland Jaycox. Roland.
Hey, Roland.
Great to meet you.
You can call me Jimmy.
Jimmy, absolutely. Hello.
Please, come on in.
Well, thank you.
What was it like
climbing that billboard?
Must've been pretty scary, huh?
Guy needed help, that's all.
You know, if I can do it,
anybody could. Heh.
Well, my hat is off
to you.
So here we are.
And patent law
is something you--?
Oh, yeah.
I do so many patent cases
I should probably just go ahead
and specialize already.
So, what do we got?
I feel silly asking this.
Yeah.
Before I show you
my invention,
would you mind signing
a non-disclosure agreement?
You got it.
Yeah. No problem.
It's my idea of a lifetime.
If Fisher-Price or Playskool
got their hands on this...
No worries.
You ready?
I may have seen
one of these before.
Not like this.
This one has
this little unit I've added.
This is my invention.
Do you have children?
No.
My wife and I
have two boys, 4 and 6.
And let me tell you,
toilet training them, nightmare.
Both times. They just didn't
wanna use the commode.
So I wired a motion sensor
to a voice chip and...
Well, no sense
getting all technical,
but it's all about
positive reinforcement.
Meet Tony
the Toilet Buddy.
And when you sit down
to do your business,
this is how he works.
TOILET:
Oh, yeah. That's the way.
Gosh, you're big.
You're so big.
My goodness, look at you.
Fill me up, Chandler.
Put it in me.
Chandler's my youngest.
Loves it.
Huh.
Give it to me, Chandler.
I want it all.
Mmm.
Ah...
Anyway, it goes on from there.
You get the picture.
Yeah. I, uh...
Yeah.
So, what do you think?
It's a little sexual maybe?
Sexual?
What does that--?
Suggestive, maybe?
Maybe that's
a better word. Heh.
Look, I'm not saying this thing
won't make you rich. I mean...
Some of your wealthier
Pacific Rim nations,
they'll love this,
the crazy bastards. Heh.
I created this
for children.
Children.
Understand?
Hey, Viagra was originally
invented to treat hypertension.
Look how that turned out.
You're completely disgusting,
you know that?
Hey, buddy, you're the one
with the sex toilet.
Get off my property!
Hey, you know what,
I hope you do make a fortune,
because Chandler's gonna need it
to help pay for his therapy.
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
[STAIR LIFT WHIRRING]
STRAUSS:
I found the Alpine shepherd boy.
[SIGHS]
[STAIR LIFT BEEPS]
No, no, you just stay put.
I'll be right over.
[SIGHS]
Oh.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Now, where were we?
Oh, would you like
some more tea?
No. No, thank you.
I'm fine.
Now, the shepherd boy
Hummel,
that's gonna go
to your nephew Clarence?
As long as he finishes college.
If he drops out,
it goes to my niece Raylene.
But then Raylene
doesn't get the girl--
The girl with the geese,
yeah, I know.
Then that would go
to your cousin Helen.
Mm-hm.
So long as she never
remarries Frederick?
Exactly.
Yeah.
And no matter what,
I want the towheaded twins
to go to Reverend Laurence's
grandson.
Um... Don't you mean
Reverend Haynes?
Because Reverend Laurence's
grandson
is going to get
the lute-playing angel,
because he was in the choir.
Very sharp, Mr. McGill.
And here I thought
all lawyers were idiots.
Heh. No, only half of us
are idiots.
The other half are crooks.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Aren't you a spicy one.
Well...
If I were 40 years younger,
I'd have you buy me
a piña colada.
Well, if you want me
to draw up a DNR,
I'll bring a blender
and some pineapple.
[BOTH LAUGH]
I knew I'd like you when I saw
how you saved that poor man
on the television.
Well...
Moxie is in such short supply
these days.
Yeah, well, I pride myself
on my moxie.
Now, I hate to do this,
but I do need
to bring up my payment.
And I'm sorry, but I can't
accept S&H Green Stamps.
[CHUCKLES]
Now, uh, my fee is $140.
A hundred and forty.
I'll gladly accept 70 today
and 70 when I come back
with the completed documents.
[SIGHS]
Twenty, 40,
sixty, 80...
a hundred
and 20...
forty.
Uh...
Okay. Ahem.
[CHUCKLES]
Shall we continue, Mr. McGill?
Yes.
Yes, we shall, Mrs. Strauss.
KIM:
Put it on the nail,
not the skin.
JIMMY:
I can't help it
if your toes are too small.
They should all be
the same size.
The size of the big toe.
That one I can do.
Yeah, that would be attractive.
Heh, heh.
So...
how's it go again?
[IMITATES TOILET]
"Oh, you're huge, Chandler.
You're a big, big boy.
Oh, where does it end?
Oh, don't stop, Chandler.
Don't stop.
Heh, heh, heh.
Oh, here it comes.
Oh, what is that?
Is that a piece of corn?
No, no. Stop.
Did you eat corn, Chandler?
Is that a niblet I see?"
Disgusting.
No. Ha, ha, ha.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Too much?
Hey, good times.
Even your lousy days are more
interesting than my good ones.
Yeah, we should definitely
do something about that.
Seriously, don't ever try
to make a living at this.
Stick with the law.
Yeah.
Because I'm really
lighting the world on fire
in that department.
Did two wills today.
Two wills, and I started
a living trust.
Whoopee.
Old people love me.
Maybe you got a future
in elder law.
You think I could handle
all that glamour?
No, I'm serious.
I've thought about getting
into elder law myself.
I watched my grandmother
at the end.
It's...
It's awful what people
have to deal with.
Insurance companies.
My scumbag cousin stealing
her savings and her pain meds.
Getting old sucks.
Seniors need someone
on their side.
[PHONE RINGING]
It's Howard.
What the hell does he want?
Shh.
Hi, Howard.
No. I mean, I haven't, uh...
Oh, my God, when?
Yeah, okay. I'll see
if I can track Jimmy down.
I'll call you back.
Sure.
It's Chuck.
[♪♪♪]
JIMMY:
Chuck. Chuck, you with me?
Chuck, hey, buddy, it's me.
Hey, can you talk to me?
Crazy sons of bitches.
Hey, sir. You can't do that.
All of this needs to stay on.
JIMMY:
No, no. No electricity,
you understand?
NURSE:
No, it needs to be on.
I'm getting security.
KIM:
No, wait, wait. Wait, wait.
No, wait, wait.
JIMMY:
Why isn't that one
going out?
Damn it.
KIM: Jimmy.
I just--
Jimmy, wait a second.
Jimmy, think.
What's the plan here?
WOMAN:
Sir, sir?
Sir, I need you to get down.
JIMMY:
What kind of torture chamber
you running here?
He's allergic to electricity.
You heard the doc. Get down.
All these lights,
you might as well
throw him into a microwave.
Come on, down.
Don't touch me.
He is this patient's brother.
Please, listen to him.
Now, hey.
Let's go.
WOMAN:
Hold on, hold on
a second, Edwin. Sir.
You ready to calm down?
Yes. His name is Jimmy,
and, yes, he is
gonna calm down.
Say the words, Jimmy.
I need to hear it from you.
I'm calm, okay?
I'm calm.
Edwin, why don't you go
wait in the hallway?
I'll call
if we need you.
Okay, so tell me
about the electricity.
Look, I know how it sounds,
but it's real.
Oh, shit.
My phone. Stuff.
Anything with a battery in it.
He can't have it near him.
Hang on.
There's my phone.
Okay, that's it.
Thanks.
Okay. What the hell happened?
Why is he here?
It started when Charles stole
his neighbor's newspaper.
What? He never leaves
the house.
WOMAN:
I don't have
all the details.
but the police found him
in a very agitated state.
He was confrontational
and incoherent.
How come you didn't call me?
Why did I have
to hear about this
through my brother's
prick of a law partner?
The only contact information
we could find
was a business card.
Jimmy, in my opinion,
Charles should be
committed
for 30 days of
psychiatric observation.
As a family member,
you can submit a petition
for him to be evaluated.
There's an excellent facility
in Las Cruces.
He can be there tomorrow.
I'd rather not.
Hey, buddy.
Hey, I'm right here.
Oh, hey, Chuck.
Excuse me.
Mr. McGill,
my name is Dr. Cruz.
Do you know why
you're in the hospital?
The police kicked in my door.
No warrant.
No cause.
I wasn't incoherent.
They just weren't listening.
They Tasered me, Jimmy.
Oh, Jesus.
Kim?
I'm sorry, I can
give you privacy.
No, no, no,
that's all right. Stay.
Howard called me.
He's very concerned about you.
How are you feeling now,
Mr. McGill?
Do--? Do you have a phone
or a pager
or anything with a battery?
I don't think so. I...
[GROANS]
Yeah. Heh.
Oversight.
Sorry about that.
Can you tell me a little more
about your...
situation?
It's not a situation.
It's a condition.
Electromagnetic
hypersensitivity.
For reasons unknown, my nervous
system has become sensitized
to certain frequencies
of electromagnetic radiation.
Your brother called it
an allergy to electricity.
Well, it's
an oversimplification.
But it's essentially
correct.
Electronic devices create
their own
electromagnetic fields.
The closer I am
to such devices,
the worse my symptoms.
Which are?
Burning sensation on my skin,
a sharp, cold pain in my bones,
muscle fatigue,
heart palpitations,
blurred vision,
tinnitus, vertigo,
nausea, shortness of breath.
A general--
It hurts.
Yes, it hurts.
When did you first experience
these symptoms?
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Oh, must have been...
You left the office
18 months ago.
Well, in that case, uh,
must have been almost two years.
Two years?
That's a--
That's a long time
to live with discomfort.
Well, there it is.
You think I'm crazy.
I never said that.
No, you didn't,
because you're very polite.
But you think it.
Otherwise you wouldn't be
talking about commitment.
You find that idea distressing?
JIMMY: Who the hell wouldn't?
I find it inappropriate
for a person
suffering from
a physical condition.
Anyone who's spent more than
a few minutes with me knows
that this isn't
some kind of delusion.
Wouldn't you agree, Kim?
JIMMY: Of course she does.
Well, I'm not a doctor.
You've known me
for a decade.
Have you ever seen me
exhibit any sign,
any sign whatsoever,
of mental illness?
See? If I thought
for one second
you could cure me, believe me,
I'd jump at the chance.
With all due respect, psychiatry
doesn't have the answers.
I'd very much like to try.
Section 43-1-11, part E3.
"The proposed commitment
is consistent
with the treatment needs
of the client
and with the least drastic
means principle."
Do you think subjecting me
to this kind of pain for a month
is the least drastic means?
JIMMY:
He might as well spend
a month in a wood chipper.
CRUZ:
I understand your frustration.
I do. You're obviously
a highly-intelligent man
in difficult circumstances.
May I ask you a question?
Just for my own interest.
Yeah.
How do you meet
the needs of daily life?
What do you do for light?
How do you prepare food?
I use white gas lanterns.
For cooking,
I have a camp stove.
I have a large cooler
I keep filled with ice.
It's not ideal, but I make do.
CRUZ:
I see.
Well, thank you.
Would you mind
if I took a moment
to speak with your brother?
Uh, make sure you still
have your wallet
when you're done. Heh.
JIMMY: Funny guy.
Heh.
Jimmy.
I wanna go home.
That was
a dirty trick.
That wasn't a trick.
It was a demonstration.
This allergy to electricity
isn't real.
It's a manifestation
of something deeper.
I'm not saying
it's 100 percent real,
but Chuck is smarter
than you and me put together,
so we're not talking him
out of this.
And I'm not sending him
to a rubber room.
No one is talking
about rubber rooms.
There are specialists--
He's seen specialists.
The best doctors.
None of them helped, not one.
So you're ready
to give up?
Who's giving up, huh?
I'm-- I'm the one doing
the heavy lifting here.
That white gas, who do you
think brings him that?
And milk and bread
and toilet paper and ice
and every other
damn thing he needs.
Is that helping
or enabling?
If you testify
in a custodial hearing,
he can get the help he needs.
That's in your power.
To be committed involuntarily,
he has to be a danger
to himself.
Or others.
And he is.
Coleman lanterns indoors?
A camp stove?
He could burn his house down,
or the entire neighborhood.
And then you're looking at
a commitment of 10 to 20 years.
What if he just hurts himself
in a household accident?
How does he call for help?
You have the power
to help your brother.
Truly help him.
Ignoring this
won't make it go away.
What would you do?
All I know is
he needs help.
[SIGHS]
Untie him.
I'm getting him out of here.
The nurse will bring you
the release forms.
Oh, boy.
Jimmy? Kim?
I found him.
I thought I'd wait
till you got here.
Great. How's he doing?
Better. Resting.
Good.
Jimmy, I want you to know
that I've talked to the DA,
and he absolutely
will not sign off
on any commitment papers.
This is a physical condition,
not a mental one.
Chuck is of sound mind.
I think we can all
agree on that.
You're a real peach, Howard.
Of course you don't want
Chuck committed.
No, I don't.
Why would I?
If Chuck were committed,
I'd become his legal guardian.
And I'd cash him out
of HHM.
Jesus, Jimmy. Now?
You wanna hash that out here?
The tanning bed must have
melted your brain if you think--
Guys, Chuck,
that's why we're here.
Yes. Let's stay
on point.
We're talking about
the well-being
of a man whom we all
love very much.
There's many factors
at play.
Spite doesn't have
to be one of them.
Know what? I was on the fence
till you showed up.
Thanks for helping me decide.
Wave bye-bye to your cash cow,
because it's leaving
the pasture.
I'm committing him.
Jimmy-- Ji-- Wait.
Jimmy, wait. Jimmy--
Jimmy, can you wait?
Jimmy, wait a second. Listen,
I agree that Chuck needs help.
And maybe it's
the right thing to do,
but you can't do it like this.
I just wanna see
that son of a bitch sweat.
It's so obvious
what he's afraid of.
I'm taking my brother home.
[SIGHS]
CHUCK: Unh.
JIMMY: There you go, buddy.
Yeah, there you go.
Okay, some steps.
One and two,
and there you go.
Hey, you're home.
All right?
Everything's gonna be all right.
You want something to eat?
Uh, some tea?
Cup of tea?
Coffee.
Coffee. Coffee it is.
Jimmy, I'm gonna need my...
I don't-- I-- I--
Oh, it's...
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
Wanna talk about this?
There's nothing
to talk about.
You took the paper,
you saw this, you got sick.
What's your point?
Chuck, I think you got sick
because you saw this story.
Whenever you think
I've done something wrong,
something questionable,
you get worse.
I didn't get sick because
I read about you in the paper.
I got sick because
I went out of my house
to retrieve the paper--
I'm too tired for
this argument, Jimmy.
I've had it too many times.
You think this is the return
of Slippin' Jimmy, but it's not.
All right.
You think the billboard thing
was unethical.
But it was promotion.
It was advertising, that's all.
Which wasn't even allowed until
five Supreme Court justices
went completely bonkers in
Bates v. State Bar of Arizona.
Ah-ha.
But in any event...
it's legal.
If you wanna advertise,
that's your business.
"Business" being
the operative word,
because I have gotten
business off of this.
Legit business:
wills, trusts.
I'm kind of starting
to specialize
in elder law.
Elder law?
Yeah. The things the elderly
have to deal with. I mean,
relatives coming after
their savings, telemarketers,
reverse-mortgage scams.
I mean, getting old sucks.
Seniors need someone
on their side,
so you're looking at him.
Oh, that sounds promising.
But it has nothing to do
with my condition.
Chuck, listen, I'm gonna
make you a promise right now.
Not necessary, not requested.
Okay. The billboard
was a one-time thing.
I'm a good lawyer.
I just needed some razzmatazz,
you know, to get the ball
rolling, some showmanship.
That's all it was.
It's done now. It's over.
All right.
From here on out,
I'm gonna play by the rules.
As any lawyer should.
Exactly.
There are clients out there
who need me,
and I'm gonna give them
the best representation
I know how to provide.
I'm on the up-and-up, okay?
I will be good.
Slippin' Jimmy,
he's back in Cicero.
Dead and buried.
Okay.
We'll see.
Where you going?
CHUCK:
Somebody's gotta
make that coffee.
I'm sure the truth
will come out,
if indeed that's what
we're all interested in.
I know everybody
in this courtroom
has strong feelings
about Nicholas Baron's past,
but I submit he is not
on trial here for his past.
He is on trial
for the murders
of Donald Kovack
and Eddie Alonzo.
JIMMY:
Single-breasted.
Light blue or cream.
It's blue.
Linen.
[♪♪♪]
Simple.
Single pocket.
[CLATTERING]
[♪♪♪]
Thank you.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Hello there.
James McGill, attorney at law.
How are you this fine morning?
I'm just fine. How about you?
Very good. Play fair.
Oh, what do we got here?
Ah, I see...
a piece is trying
to get away there.
Enjoy the Jell-O.
Get to the bottom.
Wait, who's the banker here?
That's the only one
I wanna talk to. There he is.
How are you?
Hey. I'm good.
Whoa, what a grip,
young man.
Watch out,
that's my will-writing hand.
I'm quite strong, you know.
Okay.
Hello, ladies.
You look beautiful today.
All right over there?
Very good. Play fair.
No betting.
Wait a second,
is that Veronica Lake?
Give me a hug, beautiful.
Yes. You look great today.
All right. No cheating,
no hiding the tablet.
Oh, what do we have here?
Hey, there he is.
The man in the booth.
John Wilkes Booth.
Booth Tarkington.
What you reading there?
The Complete Annotated
Book of Rules
for Parking Validation?
No.
The rules
for parking validation
are actually
pretty simple.
Most people get it
on the first try.
Well, you'll be pleased to know
I have the requisite stickers.
Be still my heart.
And...
You can have this as well.
I'm doing elder law now.
"Need a will, call McGill."
So give me a call if you, uh...
If, uh, you happen to know
any elders.
Good night.
Couldn't have a bad one
if I tried.
MIKE:
Good night.
MAN:
Have a good one.
WOMAN 1:
He drove in from El Paso,
but he made good time.
MAN:
Pick it up on pancakes.
WOMAN 2: Eggs over-medium.
WOMAN 3: Hash browns.
MAN:
Eggs over, pick it up.
[ENGINE STARTS]
LUCY [ON TV]:
Don't be so silly.
DAN: There's nobody around.
You never can tell.
DAN: Then I'll come in.
I wouldn't.
We're going to be late.
DAN: Don't be bashful, Lucy.
LUCY:
I'm not bashful, but
I've never kissed you before.
And I don't think
this is the place.
DAN:
Gosh, if you knew
how crazy I am about you,
you wouldn't hesitate.
I can't sleep.
LUCY:
Why don't you take
some hot milk?
I must be in love
because I started--
[TV MUTES]
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
MIKE:
Long way from home, aren't you?
You and me both.
[♪♪♪]