[BELL RINGING]
[SIGHS]
[DOOR OPENS]
WOMAN:
Mike.
Hey.
MIKE: Hey.
Thanks for coming.
WOMAN: Oh, yeah. Of course.
I'm just parked
across the street, so...
Okay. I was just
gonna hit the...
Yeah, sure.
I'll meet you out front.
Okay.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Janitor.
Anybody here?
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
[EXHALES]
[♪♪♪]
[GIRL GIGGLING]
GIRL: Higher.
MIKE: Higher?
Okay, you asked for it.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, sweetheart.
All right, come on down.
Pop-pop's getting tired.
Aw.
Don't "aw" me.
You take a little break.
A little break.
Go on.
A good kid.
WOMAN: Yeah, she is.
So how do you like it...
out west?
I like it.
Wide open spaces.
Yeah.
Different, anyway.
How you doing?
I'm-- Yeah, I'm okay.
You know?
Adjusting.
And Kaylee?
Yeah, she's settling in.
She still asks about him.
"Where's Daddy?"
She just misses him.
Yeah.
How long you
in town for, Mike?
I'm here...
for the duration,
indefinitely. I'm, uh...
I'm better.
And I'm sorry
it took me so long.
But I'm not like I was.
I'm back. I'm solid.
And I wanna be here for you,
for Kaylee, for my family.
That's good.
I'm glad to hear you're better.
What?
What is it, honey?
Mike, I gotta ask.
I mean...
I know I just need
to move on from this,
but I keep thinking
about something.
About what?
How before Matty died...
like, for a few weeks there,
he was...different.
Different how?
Different, I don't know.
Moody, you know?
He barely ate.
He wasn't sleeping.
He snapped at me
about the stupidest things.
I started to think
something's up at work,
or someone's sick,
something like that.
But he wouldn't talk to me.
He clammed right up.
Cops aren't real touchy-feely,
you know that.
No.
No, they're not.
No, but this wasn't the normal
"tough guys don't cry" crap.
This was more. I mean...
Did you notice?
I mean,
did you feel anything
like that from him?
No. As far as I remember,
he seemed okay.
He seemed okay to me.
Well, I started to think, I--
I don't know.
I didn't know what to think.
But then three days or four,
I don't remember,
but before he died,
there was this phone call.
Two-thirty in the morning,
I wake up
and Matty's not in bed.
And I hear him.
He's talking downstairs.
So... I go to listen
on the stairs
where he couldn't see.
He gets intense.
Like, he'd be screaming
if he wasn't whispering,
you know?
Matty didn't get worked up.
He'd let things go, but...
But this, I mean, he was angry.
He was really angry.
What was he saying?
I couldn't make it out.
It was something about...
I don't know.
I couldn't hear it.
But the next morning
I called him out.
"What the hell was that about?
What's going on?"
And he wouldn't
talk to me.
But I think...
I think
he was talking to you.
Me?
I mean, who else?
Huh?
For one hot second, I thought
maybe he was catting around--
No, he wouldn't do that.
No, I know. I know that.
But you? He knew
he could call you
anytime
he had a problem.
You were thick as thieves,
the two of you.
And there was something
in his voice.
It was
how he was talking.
It makes me think
it was you.
Stace,
I don't think it was.
I can't recall any late-night
heart-to-hearts with him.
Not around then.
Maybe it was a CI,
or a case.
Listen...
I know what you're doing.
Replaying it over and over.
Thinking, "If I'd noticed this,
or changed that,
maybe I could've
done something."
You don't think I haven't had
those thoughts? I do.
[EXHALES]
Every day.
You gotta quit
beating yourself up like this.
[SIGHS]
Matty's gone.
And that's really
all there is to it.
Yeah.
I guess that's that.
It's getting on,
I gotta get Kaylee her dinner.
Put her to bed.
Oh, yeah.
Okay. Ahem.
Well, if you want me to drop by
and keep an eye on her,
I wanna help.
See you around.
MAN:
Where to?
MIKE:
"Francisco."
FRANCISCO:
Yeah.
MIKE: You know this town?
Yeah, sure.
How well?
MAN:
You sew this up yourself?
Not bad.
Bet there's
a story there.
Isn't there always?
Yeah.
All right,
a little sting here.
Okay.
That ought to do it.
Now, you're gonna
wanna take it easy.
Keep it clean.
Keep it dry.
Let it heal.
There's a Walgreens
couple blocks over on Louisiana.
Maybe go get yourself
a sling.
You don't have one?
Heh. Sorry.
Got a cone you could put
around your neck.
It's about the same, right?
So it's gonna be 500?
Five hundred.
I can, uh, throw some pills
in for the pain.
This stuff's
essentially Vicodin.
I can give it to you
for 25 a pill.
Maybe drop the price to 15
for something a little less
human-centric.
I'm an aspirin man.
Tell you what.
Take a couple on the house.
In case
you change your mind.
You new in town?
MIKE:
Yeah.
Passing through
or sticking around?
Why?
No reason.
It's just if you're relocating
to the land of enchantment,
I know people.
I could get you some work.
I am not looking
for that kind of work.
But...
[GROANS]
...thanks.
Don't know why
it has to be this way.
Could've been friendly.
Could've talked in your house.
You really want
the formal treatment?
Lawyer.
Come on, Mike.
It's just a couple of questions.
Ain't nothing but a thing.
Lawyer.
You're not under arrest.
Did anybody here say "arrest"?
No. You wanna walk, walk.
But I gotta say, I expected more
cooperation from you on this.
Cop to cop.
Lawyer.
[SIGHS]
Fine.
What lawyer?
Ehrmantraut,
who's got him and where?
That way.
Hey, fellas,
how you doing?
James McGill.
I'm here to see my client.
What?
You look like Matlock.
No, I look like
a young Paul Newman
dressed as Matlock.
Where's my guy?
Say hello to Barney Fife.
Wrong show,
but thanks for playing.
[SIGHS]
So, what happened?
Mayor didn't give you
enough stickers?
You wanna tell me
what we're doing here?
Oh, here's your coffee.
Uh...
Hope it's good
to the last drop,
because I'm billing you
the full hour for it.
That's for you.
Oh, that's very thoughtful.
You serious? Why'd you
have me bring it to you?
All right, here's
what's gonna happen:
Those two cops out there
are from Philadelphia.
They've gone
a long way to see me.
When they come in here, we're
all gonna have a little chat.
When it's over,
the young one,
who's been writing
in his little notebook,
he's gonna take it
and put it in his jacket,
and when he does that,
I want you to take that coffee
and spill it on him.
Little accident,
that's all.
And why, pray tell,
would I do that?
Because I'm asking you to. It's
the only reason you're here.
So I'm here because you want me
to assault a police officer?
I am asking you
to take a few ounces
of lukewarm coffee
and spill it on him.
I doubt that satisfies
the definition of "assault."
But, hey,
you're the lawyer.
Right, how silly of me.
All you want is
for me to aid and abet
you ripping off
that guy's notepad,
because that's what
you're doing here, right? Huh?
What, are you nuts?
You can't be serious.
Hey, I hate to remind you
of this, but you owe me one.
The assist I gave you with
the missing persons problem.
One good turn and so forth.
You want a good turn?
Here's your good turn, okay?
I'm gonna behave
like an honest-to-God,
law-abiding,
licensed attorney.
'Cause clearly
you need one
with whatever the hell
is going on here.
Those two jokers
out in the hallway,
I'm gonna make sure they dot
their I's and cross their T's.
Everything square
and aboveboard.
That's what I'm gonna do,
and you're gonna be happy
as hell that I'm here.
But this little Juan Valdez
bump-and-dump? No.
Not gonna happen.
Hey, gentlemen,
we're prepared to indulge you.
MAN:
Detective Escalaire
will be sitting in with us
as per A.P.D. policy.
Okay with you, right?
Fine with me.
Okay.
You got your lawyer, Mike.
Can we talk already?
Great.
So like we said,
we're here looking into
this Hoffman and Fensky thing.
Yeah, whatever you can tell us.
Anything at all.
Uh, hold on, hold on.
Hoffman, Fensky.
Fill me in.
Assume I know
absolutely nothing
about my client here,
all right?
Start at the beginning.
Jesus, seriously?
Look, don't let
Mr. Ehrmantraut's dancing eyes
and bubbly bon vivant
personality fool you.
He's actually, believe it
or not, somewhat taciturn.
Shall I fan you gently
so you don't go into shock?
Start at the beginning, okay?
We're talking Book of Genesis.
Okay, Mr. McGill.
As you probably gathered,
we, Detective Sanders and I,
work for the Philadelphia
Police Department,
as did Mr. Ehrmantraut
for nearly 30 years.
Philadelphia?
Go, Eagles.
Mr. Ehrmantraut had a son, Matt,
he too was with Philly P.D.
He was a rookie officer
with about two years on the job.
He was a good cop.
Yes, he was.
About nine months ago,
he responded
to a shots-fired call
in some west-side rattrap.
Matt went in with his partner,
Officer Troy Hoffman.
They had Sergeant Jack Fensky
backing them up.
Unfortunately,
things got out of hand.
The three of them
were ambushed,
and, uh, Matt
didn't make it out.
Now, Hoffman and Fensky
returned fire,
but the shooter got away.
We chased a few leads,
shook up the usual suspects,
came up short.
I'm very sorry to hear it.
Anyways, we kept beating
the bushes, kept coming up dry,
until three months ago.
That's when Hoffman
and Fensky turned up dead
in a vacant lot
out in Nicetown.
Again, an ambush
of some kind, it looks like.
And with whoever killed Matt
out there in the wind,
we're thinking-- Well,
it's our operating theory--
that Hoffman and Fensky
were mixed up in something.
Some bad business.
And maybe that
got Matt killed.
Yeah, sorry, I gotta do
my lawyer thing here.
Uh, what does my client
have to do with any of this?
Uh, Mike,
this is a Hail Mary.
Beyond that.
I mean,
if we had any hard evidence
or leads,
we wouldn't be out here.
Is there anything
you can tell us about
what Hoffman and Fensky
were into?
Yeah, help us out, Mike.
Help us catch the bastard
who killed Matty.
I don't know much
about Hoffman and Fensky.
They were Matt's people.
I'd see them around sometimes.
I saw 'em in a bar
the night they died.
It was McClure's,
maybe The Red Dog.
Probably McClure's.
Were they drinking
with anyone?
It's a cop bar. They were
drinking with everyone.
MAN:
You see them
with anyone in particular?
I couldn't tell you.
I was...
You know how I was.
How you doing these days?
MIKE:
Feeling like I crawled out
from the bottom
of a bottle
and working hard to stay there.
Although, I've gotta say,
it doesn't help much
dredging up the past like this.
Let me ask you,
when did you come out here
to Albuquerque?
It couldn't have been, uh,
too much later.
I think it was
the very next day.
Yeah? The day after Hoffman
and Fensky died, huh?
You didn't think to, uh, stick
around once you heard the news?
I don't think I heard the news
till I was west of Kansas City.
Still, you, uh, didn't come back
for the funerals, correct?
Even though Hoffman
was Matt's partner.
SANDERS:
You remember anything
about that night at the bar?
Did you talk to Hoffman
or Fensky at all?
Sorry, I got nothing.
They weren't my people.
I'm sorry you guys took a flyer
on me. I wish it had paid off.
That it? We done here?
We're done here, yeah.
That wasn't so hard, huh?
Thanks, Mike.
Yeah.
We're probably gonna kick around
for another couple days,
in case you think of something.
I've never been out west before.
Oh, hey--
Oh! Shit.
Jeez. Sorry. Sorry.
Come on.
Got any paper towels?
Hey, I got it. Thank you.
Sorry.
[CAR STARTS]
Oh, for the love of--
You gotta do that right here?
Right in front of me?
What's so important in there
that we had to pull
that third-rate
Marx Brothers routine?
You really wanna know?
And risk getting a piece
of an obstruction rap?
No, thank you.
Anything else
you wanna ask?
How'd you know?
Know what?
That I would do that. That--
Ahem. How did you know
that I would, uh,
spill that coffee?
[CHUCKLES]
What the hell is that?
What's "heh-heh"
supposed to mean, huh?
Okay, great, you're the strong,
silent type. Hooray for you.
But in case you missed it,
your friends
from Philly back there,
they think
you killed two cops.
Yup.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
Yeah, it's me.
We need to talk.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
You call the cops?
What?
Philadelphia P.D.
Did you call 'em?
Yeah, I did.
Why?
I told them I heard about
Hoffman and Fensky--
Yeah, what?
You don't think
it's strange?
First Matt,
then not six months later,
his partner
and his sergeant?
Yeah, I called them,
to help catch Matty's killer.
Mike, what if
the same person--?
What if the piece of shit
who got Matty got them too?
And what exactly
did you tell them?
I told them--
You tell 'em Matt was dirty?
Is that what you told them?
I--
How could you
possibly think that?
That's your husband,
the father of your child.
I didn't say that.
I told them I found money.
After Kaylee and I moved here,
when I was unpacking,
it was in the lining
of an old suitcase.
Matt must have tucked it away
in there, because this was cash.
Five, six thousand,
from God knows where.
I mean, we were basically
paycheck to paycheck.
Where the hell
did he get it?
Why didn't you ask me?
Why didn't you come to me?
I couldn't.
I knew what
it would do to you.
First he's murdered,
and then for you to think...
I mean, it would burn you
to the ground.
There'd be nothing left.
And you wouldn't talk to me.
Every night you were
drinking yourself unconscious
like you were
the only one who lost him.
I don't care. He was dirty,
he was clean, I don't care.
All I want is for
whoever killed Matty
to rot in a cell
for the rest of their life.
Then I want
whatever's left of them
just dumped in the trash.
That's what I want.
I don't care where it leads,
what it uncovers.
I mean, what difference would it
make if he was anything?
I'd still love him. I'd still
miss him. He'd still be gone.
Matt wasn't dirty.
Well, so be straight with me.
Right now, this is it, Mike.
What was that phone call
before he died?
Don't bullshit me.
That was between me and my son.
So you're admitting
it was you?
He wasn't dirty!
Goddamn you, you get that
through your head!
My son wasn't dirty!
[DOOR SLAMS]
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING NEARBY]
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
INSIDE BAR]
INDISTINCTLY OVER SPEAKERS]
[CHATTERING]
[SIGHS]
Let him cry it all out,
okay?
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, Mikey.
Young Hoffman.
Mikey boy.
My brothers.
How you doing?
Brothers. Huh?
HOFFMAN:
Good to see you too.
It's been a minute.
I know.
I know it was you.
[CHUCKLES]
[ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
BARTENDER:
Closing time, Mikey.
MIKE:
Yeah, yeah, yeah, okay.
How about I give you
a lift home?
MIKE:
Mm.
I'm fine.
I can't let you drive.
Get you a cab?
No, I'm good,
I'm good.
Don't worry.
Anyway, I sold my car,
so I'm walking.
Thank you.
Albuquerque, New Mexico.
You ever been?
Nope.
Well...
That's where I'm headed.
Tarantulas, they got.
That's a big minus
in my book.
Well, I will be
on the lookout.
You take care,
my friend.
Take care.
[VEHICLE APPROACHES]
HOFFMAN:
Hey, Mike.
Mikey.
You want a ride?
I'm walking.
Pull over here.
HOFFMAN:
What you doing out here?
Come on, let us drive you.
It's colder than
my ex-wife's tit out here.
Come on, come on.
I'm walking.
Come on,
don't be an ass.
Let us take you home.
Get in the car.
It's cold out here.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Mike.
Come on.
FENSKY:
Okay, easy.
We're gonna have
you home in no time.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, that's mine.
Hey, now,
we don't want you
to shoot your foot
off now, do we?
FENSKY: Hey, Mikey.
[GRUNTS]
Mikey, you with us?
MIKE:
What?
Really tied one on good
back there, buddy.
Shit, yeah, he did.
Put it away
like they were fixing
to bring back Prohibition.
Hey.
Hey, back at McClure's,
you were talking
out your ass. Hm?
"I know it was you." Heh.
What's that supposed to mean,
huh? You think you know what?
Got something
you wanna get off your chest?
Something you wanna
say to us?
You killed him.
You killed Matty.
And you killed him
for nothing.
You killed him
because you were scared
of what you thought
he might do.
You got him
in that crack house...
and you staged it.
Made it look like
a junkie with a gun.
But it was you.
And I know it was you.
And I'm gonna prove it.
Help me get him
out of the car.
What?
FENSKY: Come on.
There you go.
Watch your head.
All right, come on, Mike, huh?
One, two, one, two, buddy.
Now, you wait there one second.
We're gonna work this whole
thing out, okay, Mikey?
So, what do we do now?
Hey, grief, it's a bitch.
He couldn't live with it,
Matt dying the way he did.
It's too much
for the old man,
so Mike here
decided to eat his gun.
It's tragic, but anyone
could see this coming.
He's drinking himself
to death.
We're doing him a favor.
MIKE:
Smart.
It's what I would've done
if I were you.
[GUN CLICKS]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
[GRUNTING]
[GURGLING]
MIKE:
You let some things slide,
you look the other way.
You bust a drug dealer
who has more cash
than you'll ever earn
in a lifetime.
Some of it doesn't make it
back into evidence, so what?
You took a taste.
So did everyone else.
That's how you knew
you were safe.
It's like killing Caesar.
Everyone's guilty.
Matt wasn't dirty.
I was.
Everyone was
in that precinct.
That's how it worked.
You turn in your buddy,
you're screwing yourself.
You go along to get along.
And you went along.
I did.
Yeah.
Okay, but you said
Matt didn't.
No.
Not Matt.
Fensky
got to Hoffman early.
Kickbacks from some gang
or another.
Protection, basically.
And Hoffman went to Matty
and offered to cut him in.
Only fair, right?
They were partners.
And Matt did
what you would think.
He agonized.
And then he came to me.
Wanted to go to the IA,
do the right thing,
shut 'em down.
Oh, my God, and you let him?
That's why he got killed?
'Cause he was gonna turn
on those guys?
No, no.
I told him...
[GRUNTS]
You know what
a cop fears most?
More than getting shot,
more than anything.
Prison.
Getting locked up
with everybody you put away.
You threaten a cop with that,
you make him dangerous.
That's what I told him.
I talked sense.
No one was getting hurt.
But if you go to the IA,
if you even look like
you're going...
He had a wife.
A kid.
Responsibilities.
Take the money,
do something good with it.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh...
I tried.
But he wouldn't listen.
[CHUCKLES]
My boy was stubborn.
My boy was strong.
And he was gonna
get himself killed.
So I told him....
I told him I did it too.
That I was like Hoffman,
getting by.
And that's what
you heard that night.
Me talking him down,
him kicking and screaming,
until the fight
went out of him.
He put me up
on a pedestal.
And I had to show him
that I was down in the gutter
with the rest of 'em.
Broke my boy.
I broke my boy.
He went to Hoffman, he took
the money, but he hesitated.
Even looking like
you're doing the right thing,
to those two, meant that
he wasn't solid,
that he couldn't
be trusted.
I got Matty
to take the money.
And they killed him
two days later.
He was the strongest person
that I ever knew.
He'd have never done it,
not even to save himself.
I was the only one.
I was the only one
that could get him
to debase himself
like that.
[CHUCKLES]
And it was for nothing.
I made him lesser.
I made him like me.
And the bastards
killed him anyway.
Hoffman and Fensky...
if they killed Matty,
who killed them?
Pop?
What happened?
You know what happened.
The question is...
can you live with it?
[♪♪♪]