Once again,
I do all the talking.
That's the only way
this works.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Hand it over.
Now, before that happens--
Hey, I've got it right here.
Is this it?
I will take that
as a yes.
Heh. Very well.
Mystery solved.
I could take you into custody
right now, you son of a bitch.
Both of you.
Whoa, whoa.
Where's this coming from?
You spilled the coffee, you
ambulance-chasing piece of shit.
Can we dial it down?
You know, just a notch?
Look, 45 minutes ago,
I'm sound asleep.
I get a call from
Mr. Ehrmantraut, he's concerned.
He's getting
threatening voicemails
from you accusing him
of petty theft.
I tell him, "Hey, we're
gonna nip this in the bud.
I don't care
what the hell time it is,
we're gonna go
talk this thing out."
And walking across
the parking lot, just now,
boom, there's a notepad,
plain as day,
lying on the asphalt where,
I can only surmise,
you accidentally dropped it,
detective.
Now, guys,
that's all we know.
Let me tell you
something, slick.
Wait till I get you
back to Philadelphia.
JIMMY:
I'm confused.
The state of Pennsylvania
can extradite people
for returning lost property?
Wow. That is one
bold legislature.
Anything
you wanna say to me
about what you
found in here? Hm?
Now that it's
all out in the open?
Maybe your daughter-in-law.
Maybe she's got
something to tell me.
Maybe. Maybe not.
ABBASI:
Yeah, we'll see.
First thing tomorrow.
You gotta figure
she wouldn't reach out to us
if she had nothing to say.
Hopefully whatever you are
didn't rub off
on the rest of your family.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Let's get the hell out of here.
MIKE: No.
I mean thanks as in
"three's a crowd."
You can go now.
You're not talking
to my client without me.
MIKE:
Yeah, he is.
Please leave now.
[SIGHS]
SANDERS:
Oh, man.
You ever have jet lag?
I guess that's
what this is.
Maybe it's
the altitude.
Could be the altitude.
We're a mile up, right?
[SIGHS]
Sorry about the kid.
He's young,
looking to make his mark.
I like him.
Your daughter-in-law,
what...?
What's she gonna tell us?
I don't honestly know.
Well, Mike,
if she's got nothing to say,
this pretty well
ends it here.
So maybe you should
talk to her before we do.
I talked.
If I were to guess, I'd say
she wouldn't tell you much.
Either way,
that's up to her.
That's the least
I owe her.
There's a lot of people
we both know
that think Fensky
got what was coming to him.
Hoffman too.
That whole precinct
was a sewer.
Wouldn't be surprised if there's
a few more early retirements.
Might be a good thing.
New blood.
Like the kid.
Yeah.
He's all right.
He's just gotta learn,
that's all.
Some rocks
you don't turn over.
[SIGHING AND GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
What'd you say to him?
Let's go.
Word for word, verbatim,
while it's still fresh.
What I said
is none of your concern.
I was speaking to a friend.
Heh, heh. You were speaking
to a homicide detective
who flew 2000 miles
to investigate
a double murder
for which you are clearly
the prime suspect.
How could you not recognize
the mind games, the scams,
the con jobs
these people play?
You used to be one of them.
So, what got said?
Right now.
Come on. I'm serious.
I know you're trying to help,
but--
Look, no, I'm trying to help me.
Those two Philly cheese steaks,
they wanna lock me up
right alongside you.
So work with me here,
for the both of us.
You're safe, counselor.
And I no longer require
your services.
You're kidding,
right?
What, you think you're
gonna defend yourself?
It's in someone else's hands.
What, like God?
No.
Please don't say
Hamlin Hamlin & McGill.
I appreciate your help.
Go home,
go to bed,
send me your bill.
Oh, I'm sending you my bill.
I'm sending you--
[CAR PEELS OFF]
You better believe it.
JIMMY:
It's me, your friendly
neighborhood ice man.
There was a run on bacon.
I'll get you next time.
Chuck, you there?
Chuck.
Chuck?
Chuck, you up there?
Hello?
CHUCK:
I'm out here.
Chuck?
One-twelve, 113, 114...
Holy shit, what are you doing?
Shh!
One-fifteen, 116, 117,
118, 119, 120.
Go, go. Inside.
JIMMY:
What the hell was that?
Just give me a second.
Ah...
[SIGHS]
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
It's an experiment,
really.
I've been attempting
to build up a tolerance
for electromagnetic fields.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's like, um...
You know, like taking
small doses of poison
to build up an immunity.
Is that a real thing?
Because that does not
sound like a real thing.
It's a real thing.
Anyway, as you well know,
there is a 60 kilovolt
transformer
200 meters south-southwest
of my front yard.
I've been trying
to get acclimated to it.
I got up to
two minutes today.
Jesus, Chuck.
Yeah.
Two days ago, I could
barely stand 30 seconds.
I'm trying to get up to
five minutes by next week.
That is just...
Uh, but why now?
After what happened with
the police and the hospital,
I almost lost everything,
Jimmy.
I can't go on like this.
I have to find a way
to get better. I've got to.
I have to get back to work.
Sitting here
rotting away.
This is no kind of
life for me. For anyone.
I need to be useful again.
Chuck,
I am so proud of you.
Oh. Heh, heh.
It'll be a long process.
But one to which
I'm very much committed.
I have to be.
[GRUNTS]
I-- I'll be right back.
I gotta get a few more
things out of the car.
All right.
[GRUNTING]
[CHUCKLES
THEN LAUGHS]
What's all this?
It's just some case files.
I'm out of room
at the office.
I don't wanna
leave them in the car.
There's a lot of
sensitive information.
You're not planning
to leave them here?
Yeah, I don't know, Jimmy.
It'll just be
for a little while.
I'm practically sleeping on
these things back at my place.
Business is that good?
Heh. It's booming.
Streets of gold. Yeah.
I'll get these out of here
as quick as I can.
I just need to file the 413s
on some of these wills
and I'll be
out of your hair.
Four-thirteens?
Personal property statements.
You mean 513s.
Yeah, sorry. I was just
working with these seniors.
Maybe the dementia's
contagious, huh? Heh.
Um...
Ahem. So, uh,
we good here?
See you tomorrow, same time.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SIGHS]
James McGill. Scott said
he'd leave the keys to 801,
the suite
that's for lease.
Here you go. Bring them
back when you're done.
Got it.
Wow, this is, like,
really nice. Ha, ha.
Why do you sound surprised?
Not surprised, no.
Just...
You know,
could you afford this?
Oh, yeah.
Are you kidding?
The seniors have been
very good to me.
I've been meaning
to expand, you know?
It's time to invest
in myself.
I figure this may be
just the place.
Well, won't you miss
the nail salon?
Oh, I could always visit,
you know, get some French tips.
[KIM CHUCKLES]
KIM:
Wow.
JIMMY:
It's a clean slate.
Put the reception desk
right here.
Uh, get some comfortable
seating for the clients.
KIM:
It's big.
A lot of offices.
JIMMY:
Yeah, I like the openness.
I feel like I can breathe
in here, you know?
It's not some
claustrophobic little closet
that smells
like acetone. Heh.
Room to grow.
Dream big, I say.
Got a decent-size conference
room. Not as big as Hamlin's,
but, you know, it's cozy.
Our elderly brethren
prefer that, I find.
Yeah. Could be
cozier though.
Maybe you could embroider
some little cushions.
Crochet a runner
for the table.
Rocking chairs all around?
Yes.
Make it look like the front
of a Cracker Barrel. Huh?
Now you're talking.
This is me.
I love it.
Gotta look successful
to be successful, am I right?
Well, this definitely
looks like success. Heh.
Great view. Get you
a big fancy desk in here.
Cocobolo desk.
A what?
I don't know what it means,
but I just like
saying the word. Cocobolo.
Okay, well, whatever it is,
you deserve it.
And I want you
to see this one.
Here we are.
Ha, ha. Whoa.
This is way better
than the other one.
You think?
Uh, yeah. Who goes in here?
Because I'd be all up
in here if I were you.
JIMMY:
Yeah. Yeah, you know,
you're right.
It is real nice.
It's a corner office.
You gotta go with
the corner office.
Saving it for someone.
Who?
Well, my partner.
Your partner? Who's...?
Who would that be?
Well, you said you were
interested in elder law.
That's-- That is so...
Thank you. Really.
But you know I've got
a lot invested at HHM.
With what's going on now,
I'm closer than ever to partner.
Like maybe two years,
and I'm in.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah, it's...
It's just a thought.
Plus, you know, they put me
through law school.
I feel like I owe them.
Actually, I do owe them,
literally, you know?
But it's a nice thought,
Jimmy.
Just, uh, you know,
playing with ideas.
I had the extra office
and everything.
Yeah, no, I get it.
I want to see
the kitchen.
Wow.
They have stainless
in here.
I don't even have
stainless at home.
KIM:
I know this is the last thing
you wanna hear.
I think your chances
of getting a favorable ruling
from a jury
are very slim.
CRAIG:
What does that mean?
We're not in a great position
to win at trial.
But we came to you people
because we were told
you win cases.
Winning doesn't always mean
getting a favorable verdict.
We try to achieve
the best outcome for our clients
given each
individual case.
Frankly, we've worked very hard
to stave off an arrest,
after the misunderstanding
about your, uh, camping trip.
The DA was concerned
you might be a flight risk.
Heh. Flight risk?
We were practically
in our own backyard. Heh.
That's exactly
what we told the DA.
We've managed
to come up with a deal
that is favorable
under the circumstances.
Deal. I hate that terminology.
A deal is what they got O.J.
Maybe we should hear it.
It's a terrible term.
What kind of deal?
If the prosecution
decides to file,
which is the direction
this seems to be headed,
and if they choose
to stack charges, Craig,
you're looking at 30 years
in prison.
Thirty years?
KIM: That's the maximum.
Given the nature of the charge
and political environment,
I'd say we should expect it.
The public outcry in cases like
these is a big factor. However,
after much discussion
with the DA,
who is also invested in keeping
the press to a minimum,
we have arrived
at an arrangement
which would
include 16 months
in a county facility.
Sixteen months?
Down from 30 years.
And you most likely
wouldn't serve all of it.
But he would have to say
he was guilty.
Admitting wrongdoing and
making the county whole again
goes a long way,
hence the minimal sentence.
Making the county whole again?
It includes the stipulation
that you return
$1.6 million
in misappropriated funds.
Give back the money?
There is no money.
We told you
Craig is innocent.
I understand. However,
I'd like to emphasize again
that this deal is Craig's best
chance of minimizing jail time.
You're telling us
there are drug dealers
and murderers
walking the streets,
but instead of them, they wanna
put an innocent man in jail?
There's no other way?
I'm sorry.
I think under the circumstances,
this is your best option.
Murderers and rapists,
and this is how they--?
Okay. There is no money.
There never was.
You have to take this to trial.
KIM: Look,
you have a difficult,
but nevertheless straightforward
choice to make here.
On one hand,
you give up the money--
Ah-- I just told you,
there is no money.
Plead guilty.
It's painful, I know.
And go to jail for a year and
a half. But your other choice,
that is no choice at all.
If you go to trial,
you'll most likely lose,
and Craig goes to prison
for decades.
Your children will
grow up seeing their dad
through bars
on visiting day.
I know what I'd do.
I'd take the deal.
Two years from now,
you can be starting over.
It's tough, I know.
But you're tough people.
And your family
is worth it.
Why don't I give you
a few moments to discuss this?
I know it's a big decision.
We don't need
to discuss it.
You're fired.
How about we go to my office
and discuss this?
There's a solution.
That won't be necessary.
We will no longer be
requiring your services.
It's not personal.
If you're unhappy,
there may be other directions.
We are done.
Please stop following us.
Don't look back, honey.
Only look forward.
Always in life, look forward.
JIMMY:
O-70. O-70.
Oh, yeah. Seventy's a good age.
All right, duck your heads,
because here comes
another number.
N-32.
And the action never stops.
I hope you all
took your heart pills,
because it's almost
too much excitement, right?
Which one will it be?
Say your prayers,
here it comes.
All right. We've got G-48.
G, as in Guy Lombardo. G-48.
Keep your elbows to yourselves,
okay?
No body-checking.
All right, what do we have here?
Wait for it.
B-6.
Lucky B-6. Just like
the vitamin. All right?
Which you should be taking.
Keep things moving
in the old GI tract.
Bingo.
JIMMY: Oh, we have a winner.
[BELL DINGING]
Lady Luck has struck again.
Let's see a hand,
so we know who's won.
It's the lovely young lady
in the back.
Congratulations, miss,
you've won a, um...
What do we have
for the lovely lady?
A notebook.
Yeah,
it's an adorable notebook.
Do you like cats, Miss...?
Oh, oh. Irene. I love kitties.
I have two Siamese cats,
Oscar and Felix.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Felix can wash himself.
Oscar won't.
He-- He just won't.
What a lovely story.
Thank you. Um...
Can you take that to Irene,
and when you come back, cover?
I'm gonna take
a short break,
because somebody needs
legal help. Heh, heh.
[JIMMY CLEARS THROAT]
[IN FOREIGN ACCENT]
Offices of James McGill,
Esquire.
How may I direct your call?
Yes, yes, of course.
Um, one moment, please.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Déjà vu, hello again.
Good to see you.
CRAIG:
Nice to see you.
So how may I be of service?
We would like to hire you
as our attorney, Mr. McGill.
Wow. Really?
BETSY:
However, we have
certain conditions.
And these are not
up for debate.
We want no jail time.
Zero.
Craig is innocent
and we expect you to prove that.
We won't see his name
smeared like this any longer.
Um, can we back up
just a scootch?
Because last time we spoke,
you were very enthusiastic--
You were positively insistent.
--about being represented
by HHM.
Well-- Oh.
That's all right.
We've parted ways.
May I ask why?
We disagreed with
their defense strategy.
Okay.
They treated us
like we were guilty.
So your previous objections to
my representing you are now...?
Oh, I'm sorry about my bluntness
at our last encounter.
Unfortunate.
Mm-hm.
CRAIG:
Yeah, we really--
We're very sorry about that.
We thought long and hard
about it, and, um, we...
You know,
given your passion
and your can-do attitude,
we really--
We just believe you're
the lawyer for us.
For us, yes.
Well, as flattered as I am by
this, um, since we last spoke,
I've changed
my area of specialization.
So I concentrate
on elder law now.
CRAIG:
But I mean, you said that
you would fight for us.
Yeah, you--
You were adamant.
You promised to get us
a not-guilty verdict.
I don't think
I exactly promised that.
BETSY:
You said we would be
Client Number 1,
morning, noon or night.
Yes, and I meant what I said.
At the time.
But times change.
But we've already paid you
a retainer.
Right. A retainer.
That is what you called it.
That was your
specific terminology.
Could you excuse me
for a moment?
I had a Big Gulp
on the way over.
Oh. Ha, ha.
[MAN URINATING]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
KIM: Hey.
Hey there.
Funny story. I found something
that belongs to you. Again.
Yeah? What?
Who?
Picture The 25th Hour starring
Ned and Maude Flanders.
Oh, Christ, the Kettlemans?
You lose any other clients
today? Yeah.
Mr. and Mrs. Cuckoo-Bananas
just offered me
the plum job of defending them.
They came to you?
Yeah, I know.
I don't know what you did
to piss them off,
but it must have been good.
What did they tell you?
Not much.
Just that you treated them
like they were guilty.
Heh. Jesus.
Look, Jimmy,
I know--
I know this is a lot to ask,
but you have to convince them
to come back to HHM.
I do, huh?
Yes.
Please. It's important.
What's it worth to you?
Jimmy, I'm serious.
They left because they think
they can win this case,
but they can't.
I managed to scrape together,
from practically nothing,
I might add,
a deal they should
feel lucky to have.
This is their
absolute best bet.
Please?
Make them understand
it's better for them
if they come back.
Tell me about this deal.
Elder law?
I don't know what that is.
Yeah. Me neither.
Elder.
What do you do with--
Maybe if we were older--
Sorry. Whoo.
Oh.
Ha-ha-ha. Right?
The mysteries of the bladder.
Ha-ha-ha.
So how do we get started?
Do you need us to sign
that little paper?
I am-- I am very sorry, but I'm
afraid I can't take your case.
My schedule is just--
It's just chock-full right now.
I highly encourage you
to go back to HHM.
I'm certain they would
welcome you with open arms.
No, we're not
going back there.
They were incompatible.
I understand. They asked you
to face some harsh realities.
And I get it.
No one likes that.
But bottom line here,
Kim Wexler is a fine attorney.
She has a great relationship
with the DA.
Much as I'd love
to sing my own praises,
I doubt I could
get you a deal
as good as the one
she already has.
Okay.
We don't want a deal.
We want you, our lawyer,
to exonerate Craig.
Exonerate? That is a big word,
particularly in your case.
But there will be
no deal.
There is no money
with which to make a deal.
Can we all three just parachute
down from Cloud Cuckooland?
Because we know without
question there is money.
I distinctly remember
a spirited game
of tug-of-war
over this money,
money which we then
discussed at length.
You made many excuses justifying
your possession of said money.
It's there. It exists--
BETSY: But that--
Shh, shh! Just,
please, for my own sanity.
You can't hide
a big bag of cash forever,
and you certainly will never
be able to spend any of it.
So go back to HHM,
apologize to Ms. Wexler,
and for chrissakes,
take the deal.
If there were any money--
Lady, enough.
If there were any money,
there would have to be
a full accounting of it.
Every penny
would have to be present.
Every single penny.
You understand?
All of it.
That includes the 30,000--
Craig, yes, he gets it.
CRAIG:
Yeah, he gets it.
We are in this together,
Mr. McGill, come what may.
Now, where do we begin?
[CHATTERING
AND PHONES RINGING]
There you go. Kettleman.
That's all of it.
Where's Kim?
Oh, we moved her over
to the east wing.
The east wing?
That's the cornfield.
Why are you sending her
to the cornfield, Howard?
Never heard it
called that before.
Well, that's what
you call it.
You're gonna
punish her because
you lost those
batshit Kettlemans?
You notice I'm
not exactly crowing over
how I snaked them
away from you.
Jimmy,
here are your files.
I'm not gonna discuss
my employee policies with you.
I'm gonna need some help here.
Yeah.
You sure are.
JIMMY:
That prick firing you?
KIM:
Best-case scenario
is my two-year plan
just became
a ten-year plan.
JIMMY:
That schmuck.
You didn't do anything wrong.
KIM: I lost a client.
JIMMY: Not your fault.
They're not really playing with
a full deck, those Kettlemans.
You had to take their case?
I'm sorry, okay? I tried.
I really did.
I'm not being fair.
Of course you tried.
They'll do
what they wanna do.
Hope you didn't
promise them too much.
I doubt you'll be able to do
more for them
than we were offering.
You think very highly
of my skills, obviously.
It's not that, Jimmy.
It's a loser case.
That deal was
their best chance.
After I worked my ass off
finagling with the DA,
it's just, like...
Whatever.
There's gotta be a way,
you know?
I take it to court--
You'll lose.
Kettleman did a terrible job
covering his tracks.
For starters,
they've got reams of checks
he wrote
for false expenses.
I can't even challenge
their admission into evidence,
because he wrote them
to himself.
We're never supposed to say
our clients are guilty
but, hey,
not my client anymore.
He's guilty as sin.
Yeah, but there has to be
something. Some loophole or...
None that I could find.
There has to be a way.
Not without the money.
It's the only chip
those Kettlemans have.
They refuse to play it.
[SIGHS]
[HAND THUMPS THEN SIGHING]
[♪♪♪]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
ANNOUNCER [ON RADIO]:
--in the top of the second
inning. First pitch,
curveball for a strike.
The count is 0-and-1.
[ANNOUNCER CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO]
[GRUNTS]
--is made. Rennings throws,
and it is a liner toward
the gap in right-center field.
[ANNOUNCER CONTINUES SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[♪♪♪]
Jesus.
Gets bigger
every time I look at it.
Thanks for not heading
to the Bahamas with this.
What are you doing?
"The right thing."
You know
where you're going?
Yeah. Ahem.
Am I correct in assuming
we're now square?
Square.
[SIGHS]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Good morning.
BETSY: Who is it, Craig?
Oh, it's Mr. McGill.
Good morning. Come on in. Heh.
Oh, I love what you've
done with the place.
Last time I was here, it was,
uh, well, not a contender
for the cover of Good
Housekeeping, that's for sure.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Do you have news about our case?
I do, in fact.
But before we get
to the nitty-gritty,
I think we should
chat about your deal.
Ah-- We told you,
there will be no deal.
You did, didn't you?
However, circumstances
have changed.
What circumstances?
To answer that, um,
might I suggest
that you go check on that money
you insist you didn't take?
[CHUCKLES]
In the upstairs bathroom,
under the sink?
Wait. How could you--?
Betsy?
BETSY: No, no, no.
CRAIG: It's okay, Betsy.
It's gotta be-- It's gotta
be in there somewhere.
What did you
do with it?
By "it," you mean...?
BETSY: Where is it?
Oh.
You mean the money.
Uh, let me see. Uh...
It's on its way to
the DA's desk right about now.
What? You--?
You thief.
Takes one to know one,
doesn't it?
You took it?
How did you take it?
A good magician
never reveals his secrets.
Now, here's what
we're gonna do.
Oh, you don't tell us what
to do. You stole from us. We--
We will have you arrested.
Uh, I can see
how upset you are,
and even on a good day,
you and logic are:
[WHISTLES]
But think about
what you just said.
Criminals have no recourse,
and you two?
You're criminals. Big time.
How dare you?
Luckily, you have
a very talented lawyer
who has found a way
to minimize the damage
you've brought upon yourselves.
Oh, you're fired.
Oh, I quit already.
No, I'm talking about
Kim Wexler.
Now, you're gonna
go back to her,
apologize for your
hasty decision
to terminate her services,
and you're gonna fall on her
mercy and take that deal.
We'll tell about
the bribe you took.
JIMMY:
You could do that.
You absolutely could,
and I'd be in a mess of trouble,
a real pickle.
But so would you,
Mrs. Kettleman.
Because right now only
Mr. Kettleman is on the hook
for the whole
embezzlement kerfluffle.
But the bribe-- We're back
to calling it a bribe?
Yeah, that implicates
you as well.
It does not. It was all me.
JIMMY:
No, it wasn't. I'll make
sure everyone knows that.
[SIGHS]
Look on the bright side,
you know?
They could work out some kind of
inter-prison visitation program.
The occasional conjugal.
Maybe it won't be all bad.
You, you'll probably wind up
running your own gang.
Thing you folks
need to know about me?
I got nothing to lose.
Christ,
you should see my office.
No, it's not over.
Let's find another lawyer.
Oh, Betsy.
No, no. No.
We don't have to
put up with this.
I will not be treated this way.
Betsy.
The kids.
The--
We have to do this
for the kids.
They can't lose us both.
Oh...
[BETSY SOBBING]
CRAIG: We have to.
BETSY: No.
CRAIG:
Shh, shh.
[SOBBING]
It's okay.
It's okay. Shh, shh.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[MOUTHS]
Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING AND KICKING DOOR]
[PANTING]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[IN FOREIGN ACCENT]
Law offices of James M. McGill.
How may I direct your call?
[♪♪♪]