[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
JIMMY: Hey, Gene.
Thanks, Jimmy.
JIMMY: Trina.
Hey, Jimmy.
JIMMY:
Got a package, Dan.
[MOUTHS]
Thank you.
How's it going?
What's up?
[KNOCKS]
Hey.
Hey, yourself.
Jimmy, I'm really slammed.
Just tell me what you need.
What is it?
I can't open it.
[SIGHS]
So, what does it say?
[LAUGHS]
"I must call to your
attention the newly passed
"Environmental Impact and
Sustainability Assurance Act,
"a statute that as you know,
went into effect
without any ex post facto
provisions in place."
You got a second?
Not really. I'm--
It'll just take two seconds,
I promise.
All right.
What's this?
[SNORTS]
Is this a joke?
Nope. No joke.
You passed the bar?
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah. I did.
I thought if Kim can do it,
maybe I can too, you know?
So I got my last
few credits for undergrad
from a community college.
They're not just
for draft dodgers
and yoga classes,
all right?
Then I found
a law school
that would accept me.
I mean, it wasn't Georgetown
or anything, but...
[SIGHS]
The University
of American Samoa.
Oh, correspondence school.
Well, I wasn't gonna
quit work, right?
Nights. Weekends.
You know.
They call it distance learning
nowadays. They're accredited.
Go, Land Crabs.
So you know, I did that.
And the bar exam's a mother.
I mean, for me, it was.
I failed it
the first two times,
but I guess it's like
losing your virginity.
Third time's the charm.
This must have
taken you years.
And you kept it a secret
all this time?
Why? You didn't come to me
for help?
Jesus, Chuck.
You're the busiest guy I know.
You're doing
important shit.
[LAUGHS]
Wow.
I don't know what to say.
Are you proud of me?
Hmm? Um...
Yes.
Absolutely.
Thanks, Chuck.
That means a lot.
Oh, hey. I was hoping,
you know,
if you think
it's appropriate,
once I get sworn in and
everything, consider hiring me.
As what? Oh, a lawyer.
Obviously. Yeah.
Well, that's a question
I'm gonna have to take up
with Howard
and the other partners.
Uh, you know,
it's not my decision alone.
But how could they say no?
So much drive.
Jimmy, look what
you've done here.
[LAUGHS]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING AND CLAPPING]
KIM:
I told those guys devil's food.
JIMMY:
I will sue the store for you.
KIM: Good.
BURT: Just remember us
when you're all big time.
JIMMY:
I don't remember you now, Burt.
MAN:
You representing mail room,
so you show those upstairs
jackholes how it gets--
Hey. What're you folks up to?
Having a party?
KIM:
Just a little celebration
on behalf of New Mexico's
newest attorney.
I heard. Jesus, Jimmy.
You're a regular Charlie Hustle.
Congratulations, my friend.
Oh, thank you.
Would you like some cake?
Oh, here.
Um, don't mind
if I do.
Really, really impressive,
Jimmy.
We're all proud of you.
Hey, I hate
to interrupt,
but could you guys
give Jimmy and me a moment?
Sure.
Yeah. Absolutely.
[COPIER WHIRRING]
Please, sit down.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Let's reassess
in six months.
Thanks for understanding,
Jimmy.
You want the door open
or closed?
Closed.
[♪♪♪]
[KNOCKS]
How's it going?
Settling back in.
Great.
So apparently
they are ready for us.
Oh. Thanks.
But I wanted to get a couple
of things done before lunch.
And I'm still trying to--
Come on, Kim.
You deserve this.
Come bask in the glow.
HOWARD:
Thank you all for coming.
I appreciate you making time in
the middle of your busy days.
I'm pleased to announce
that working closely
with the Bernalillo County
District Attorney's Office,
we've reached a plea agreement
for treasurer Craig Kettleman.
We believe this is a just
and fair outcome,
and brings to a close
an incident
Mr. Kettleman
deeply regrets.
He is committed
to making amends...
Can I help you?
Yeah. I'm here to see
Mrs. Landry.
Ah.
Sign in right here,
please.
Are you a relative?
Lawyer.
Ahem. But I treat my clients
like family.
You know where
to find her?
Yeah. Thanks.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER TV]
Hey. Good morning, folks.
Hi. Jimmy McGill.
Uh, oh. Hey. Pick a card,
any card.
All right.
How's it going there?
Good. Whoa, not so tight.
Oh. Shh.
A little surprise
from the card fairy.
Give me that squeeze.
Squeeze whatever you got
that's below the water
that I can't see. Oh, yeah.
All right,
Mrs. Landry.
Just a few more
signatures and, uh,
ahem, thy will be done.
Would you like
another Hydrox?
No, thank you.
I'm all Hydrox'd out.
Oh, well, please help yourself
if you change your mind.
All right. That one.
Okay. And that one.
And that is it.
Oh. What a relief.
I should have done this
years ago.
Well, people do tend
to put it off.
But everybody
should have a will.
Please tell your friends.
And that comes to $140.
And I'm happy to take
cash or a check.
Or, uh, cash.
[CHUCKLES]
One moment.
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
Could you write me a check?
Well, it's been so long,
I really don't know if I have
enough in my account.
I am so sorry.
This is awful.
But all I have is $43.
Okay.
Now, I could ask
for an advance.
I-- I am so sorry.
It's fine.
I don't know what to say.
This is awful.
Oh. You could keep the will
until I get my allowance.
And that should only be
until the end of next week.
That's not necessary.
Here's my address.
Just mail it to me
when you've got it. All right?
And why don't we--
We'll just make it an even 120.
All right?
Oh. Thank you.
You have a nice day.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Excuse me. Allowance?
Your family has you
on an allowance?
No. No. It's--
It's my money.
I just get it
from Sandpiper Crossing.
Five hundred dollars a month--
I don't understand.
You should have
social security checks
plus that pension
we talked about.
So how are you
on an allowance?
Well, the checks
go to Sandpiper.
And then they take out
my fees and my expenses.
Why don't you just
come on in?
I'm afraid I'm not
explaining it very well.
I-- I have statements here.
Somewhere. Somewhere.
So your pension
and social security
goes straight
to the Sandpiper people?
They take out--
They take out what they need.
And then I get
my allowance.
Here. And all the rest
goes into my savings account.
It's really all
very above-board.
A lot of places
do it this way.
This is how they do it
for everybody around here?
Well, yes. They-- They try
to make everything easy for us.
Mrs. Landry, are any of your
friends around
who I could talk to?
MAN [OVER TV]:
And okay. I said, "What?"
So I went in the house,
I told the house...
I could not find...
[INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER TV]
JIMMY:
In order to find out,
you have to look
on the back.
Okay. And see this key.
See, you have reading glasses.
Could I borrow your glasses?
Yes.
Thank you.
Oh, these are gonna
help me,
but I don't know
if they'll do the trick.
[CHUCKLES]
So tiny.
Four. Ten. Twelve.
I think it might be Q-tips.
I can't tell.
It's probably an accident,
but we should look into it,
don't you think?
They're not doing this
intentionally, okay?
This could be a mistake.
If we correct the mistake,
then you'll get some money back.
And it'll be fair.
[DOOR CLOSES]
JIMMY:
Hey, Chuck.
My boxes.
The ones I left--
Oh.
Sandpiper Crossing.
Did you do my wills?
CHUCK: Yes, I did.
JIMMY:
Hey, would you look at that?
Thank you.
CHUCK: Don't thank me.
This was a one-time thing.
And don't think I don't see
what you were doing here.
You wanted to play Tom Sawyer,
wanted me to paint the fence.
God help me,
it worked.
You need help? Hire a paralegal.
Stand on your own two feet.
Yeah. Sure.
I'll do that.
You're not even
listening to me.
No. I hear you,
Chuck, okay?
Self-reliance. Great stuff.
Would you look at this?
What did I just say?
Take a look, okay?
Just right here.
Do you see what I see?
[SIGHS]
All I'm asking is for you
to take a look. Please?
Sandpiper Crossing.
It's a retirement home,
assisted living.
This is one of their invoices
they send their residents.
What exactly
am I looking for here?
Nothing earthshaking.
Just little things.
Little things like--
Like this right here.
Fourteen dollars
for code 118-62.
What's 118-62?
I wonder.
How could you
even read this?
It's like microfilm.
[CHUCK SIGHS]
118-62 is facial tissue.
Fourteen bucks
for a box of Kleenex.
JIMMY:
Yeah. And I found others.
There's three and half dollars
for a single roll of toilet
paper, 22 bucks for aspirin.
It's a clear pattern
of overcharging.
Nothing huge
but adds up to real money.
I mean, here, look.
This woman, she got soaked
for, like, 400 bucks last month.
And there's a pretty
solid attempt
at concealment
of that fact.
Which, to my way of thinking,
makes it--
Fraud.
This was in work I did?
Yeah. You must have
missed it.
Um... Look, Chuck.
I got lucky, right?
Even a stopped clock
is right twice a day.
This is no mom and pop outfit,
okay? I dug around a little.
They're owned by some kind of
real estate investment trust.
I'm working on getting more info
but this could be big.
I mean, this could be
a big case, right?
Well, if it's more
than a few errant billings,
and if it's systematic
and you establish a pattern,
it could be class-action.
What do I do now?
I mean, what next?
Well, you need
more information.
You don't want to go off
half-cocked.
Full cock.
Okay. Now, I'm gonna
head back there. Thank you.
You're the best.
Back to see Mrs. Landry.
Okay.
What gives?
Sorry, sir. New policy.
We're concerned about
solicitation on the premises.
I'm not a gigolo
if that's what you're implying.
Legal solicitation.
We are obligated to protect our
residents from being harassed.
And we have the right
to refuse entry.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
I have clients
in there now.
They have a legal right
to meet with me.
Well, you'll just have to
arrange to meet them elsewhere.
Oh, come on, guys.
Seriously?
What, are you making
Soylent Green back there? It's--
All right. Okay.
I-- I'm backing away.
Yeah?
You know what? Um...
Hey, this has gotten me a little
bit stirred up down there.
Can I use your restroom?
Please. I've got IBS.
Go ahead.
[♪♪♪]
"To Sandpiper Crossing.
Clients of James M. McGill,
this is to inform you--"
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
PAULA:
Sir, are you all right in there?
JIMMY:
"We believe that--"
"Breach of contract--"
Come on now, sir.
I've been very patient.
"Clear pattern
of malfeasance--"
"Negligent infliction
of emotional stress."
Sir, I really need you
to finish up and come out.
"Contact by the end of the week
or I will be forced
to move forward."
I need you to finish--
This is a demand letter
informing Sandpiper Crossing
of pending litigation
for defrauding my clients
through systematic overcharging.
You're shredding in there.
I'm not deaf.
I can hear you.
Stop right now.
This here. This makes it
official, all right?
If you don't stop shredding now,
that's destruction of evidence.
Spoliation, that's what
it's called. And it's a felony.
So call your lawyers right now
and tell them I said that. Me.
James McGill, Esquire.
I'm telling you, guys.
Big mistake.
[YELPS]
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hey.
STACEY: Hey.
Am I calling at a bad time?
No. Not at all.
How you doing?
Yeah, pretty good.
Getting by.
How about you?
It's good to hear from you.
Yeah. I've been--
There's been a lot going on.
You know how it is.
Yeah. I know.
Uh, listen,
I was--
Was hoping maybe
you could do me a favor.
Do you think
you could watch Kaylee?
It'd be during my shift,
the day after tomorrow.
I hate to ask,
but my regular sitter's down--
Anything you need,
I'll be there.
You can get off work?
I don't want to impose
or anything.
No. Anytime.
It's not an imposition.
Thanks.
Appreciate it.
Yeah. No problem.
At quarter to 2?
I'll see you then.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
Jesus.
[COUGHS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[SPITS]
Come on.
Where is it?
Oh. Oh...
Oh. Goddamn it.
[MUFFLED CONVERSATION]
It's not like we're close
to being done.
I mean, can't you get
somebody else to do it?
Right. They don't pay any of us
enough for this shit.
And it's going on and on.
And so I'm like:
"Why are you making
your problems my problems?"
Right. Like you don't have
problems of your own.
MAN:
Exactly. That's exactly
what I'm saying. Thank you.
[CONVERSING INDISTINCTLY]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[WHISPERING]
James McGill.
MAN [OVER PHONE]:
Mr. McGill, Rich Schweikart
of Schweikart and Cokely.
We're the law firm
representing Sandpiper Crossing.
How are you this evening?
Quite well, thank you.
How are you?
Doing fine. Doing fine.
I'm sorry to call so late.
Did I catch you at a bad time?
No. No. No. It's fine.
It's just that
you're whispering.
I'm at the opera.
Oh. What opera?
Magic Flute.
Mozart. Lovely.
Well, I'll try not to keep you.
We received something
from you today
and we're not
quite sure what.
It's a demand letter.
Ah. It was a little confusing
because it was written on--
Well, I had to write it quickly,
because your clients were in the
process of destroying evidence.
Mr. McGill, if you're talking
about shredding documents,
that's neither irregular
nor illegal.
Every business in America
does it.
You say potato,
I say spoliation.
Mm-hm. Maybe walk me through
what you're alleging here.
I believe it's all
in the letter.
I'm not saying it's not.
But it's a bit hard to read.
Next time,
I'd use double ply.
Let's not fixate on the medium,
okay? Let's look at the message.
Your clients are facing
multiple counts of elder abuse,
and fraud, and deceptive
and unfair trade practices.
And that's just the start, okay?
I'm not a betting man,
but I'd bet I'll find more.
Mr. McGill, are you related
to Charles McGill?
He's my brother.
Yeah? How's he doing
these days?
I fail to see the relevance
of this.
Frankly, the only reason
that I made this phone call
was out of respect
for Charles
on the off chance
you might be related to him.
My partner suggested
that the best response
would be to send a Rule 11
letter and have you sanctioned.
But I didn't want
to jump to that immediately.
How about you stop trying
to rattle my cage
and just, you know,
respond to the merits?
This is my response,
Mr. McGill.
You have no good-faith basis
to threaten litigation.
This is a shakedown
and we both know it.
Now, if you push this any
further, my hands will be tied.
I'm sorry
for interrupting your evening.
Enjoy the Magic Flute.
[PHONE BEEPS OFF]
Blow my magic flute.
[TRASH SQUISHING AND RATTLING]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
[SPITTING AND COUGHING]
[PANTING]
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
Jimmy, what're
you doing here?
Oh, Chuck. I'm sorry
to show up like this.
I just needed space
to work.
What is all this?
What have you done
to my dining room?
They were spoliating,
the Sandpiper people.
They wouldn't let me in.
I could see they were shredding.
I wrote them a demand letter
and gave it--
You broke into a nursing home?
Assisted living.
And you stole their garbage.
No, it was in public.
There was no lock, no nothing.
I just lifted the lid
and there it was.
There's
no reasonable expectation
of privacy
in that situation, is there?
You can't say it's private if
a hobo can use it as a wigwam.
That's the standard, right,
if animals
or vagrants can get in?
More or less, yes.
Okay, so this is all legal.
It's completely
above-the-belt legal.
I just need to figure out
what they're trying to cover up.
You don't shred like this unless
you got something to hide.
Not necessarily.
Oh, come on, Chuck.
A lawyer shows up,
starts figuring out
their little scheme.
And suddenly this?
No, it's not a coincidence.
It's in here.
Well, at least
it's not cross-cut.
Look, you won't even know
I'm here, okay?
I just need some space
and some quiet.
And I'll be out
of your hair as soon as--
Stop. Stop.
It's okay.
You can work here.
Thanks.
I don't mind the company.
You look like you could
use a cup of coffee.
Good God, yes.
I'll put it on.
Up, up. Up.
Shh, shh, shh.
[SIGHS]
God's sweet sake.
Oh, good. You're up.
Well, Jesus, Chuck,
how long have I been asleep?
Chuck,
how did you--?
I can't believe this.
Uh, thank you.
This is a huge help.
I felt like I was
shoveling snow in a blizzard.
Well, it gets better.
What's this?
It's your smoking gun.
It's an invoice for syringes.
Yes. From?
Morrissey Medical Supply.
Lincoln, Nebraska.
So?
Trust me.
Meanwhile, we need
to start pulling case law.
Any precedent dealing
with 18 U.S.C. 1961 to '68.
Probably not a bad idea to pull
30-47-1 from NMSA. Uh, 1978.
I don't think
that's gonna play, really.
But it's a good
opening salvo for us.
Wait. "Us"?
We're working together
on this?
Mm. That's up
to you, Jimmy.
[CHUCKLES]
All right. All right.
All right.
Let's get to work.
[PHONE RINGING]
Kim Wexler.
JIMMY: Hey, gorgeous.
Oh, man. Sweet talking
right out of the gate.
You want something.
Make it fast. I want to go home.
Okay. Okay. Will you look
something up for me on Westlaw?
Please?
You're lucky I'm a pushover.
All right. Hit me.
Thank you.
Anything on Sedima v. Imrex.
Schlesinger v. Disney.
Holmes v. SIPC.
Whoa, slow down. Slow down.
--v. Disney.
Holmes v. SI--
PC, yeah.
Anything on 5712,
1 through 24, NMSA, 1978.
Ah, okay.
It would help if I knew
what you were
looking for, here.
Anything. Everything.
You want me to just
read you the headnotes?
No. No. Print it. Full cases.
And any cases
that cite to those cases.
Shepardize like
the wolf's at the door.
Jesus, Jimmy. That's
gonna be thousands of pages.
Pretty please
with sugar on top?
Come on. You owe me one.
Yes, I do.
But this is gonna take hours.
And who do I bill it to?
Bill it to Howard.
I still remember
his code, 1933.
Same year Hitler
came to power.
You're not funny.
I'm not billing it to my boss.
How about yours?
I'll pay you back.
Jimmy, this is three, four
hundred bucks worth of printing.
The accountants will find it,
and I'll get fired.
Which sounds fun, but no.
Okay. Hold on a sec.
Hey. Kim can't print
without a code.
Should I go there,
take notes, come back?
No, no. It'd take too long.
Use mine, 1868.
Yeah.
1868, use that. It's Chuck's.
You're using Chuck's number?
Does Chuck know you're
using Chuck's number?
We're working on something.
Bring it over
to his place after.
You're a lifesaver.
Wait. You're working a case
together?
Yeah. Keep this under your hat.
But it's gonna be huge.
Maybe a class-action, even.
We think it will settle
for one, maybe two million.
How does that work?
Chuck's a partner at HHM.
So what? I know Chuck's
partnership agreement.
He can work
with outside parties.
That clause is intended for
small-time stuff,
pro bono cases.
So I'm bono.
I'm very bono.
Chuck's a rock star.
They'll work it out.
And Chuck can handle this?
Last time I saw him, he was--
Last time you saw him,
he wasn't himself, okay?
This is good for him.
Okay.
What?
I don't know.
I'm just--
Whatever.
I'll see you in a couple hours.
Okay. We're ordering a pizza.
I'll save you a slice.
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]
Hey, you know,
if you don't separate those,
you're gonna
end up with brown.
[DOOR OPENS]
STACEY: Hello?
Hey.
We're in here. Oh...
We're playing sculptor.
She's Michel-angelina.
How's work?
Oh, you know. Work.
How'd it go?
Kid's a dream.
She's easy.
And you better
stay that way.
[STACEY CHUCKLES]
How you doing,
sweetie, huh? Huh?
Well.
I better be going.
Oh, wait.
Hang on a sec, would you?
I wanna talk
to you about something.
What's up?
I wanna know what
I should do with this.
I've been carrying it
around for weeks.
Like, holding on to it.
Every place
I put it feels wrong.
I thought about putting it
in the collection plate,
but that seemed,
I don't know...
Look, with Matty gone,
I have expenses.
And the death benefit
helped, but...
What I wanna ask you is...
can I spend this?
Stace...
if this money helps you
and Kaylee,
if it does a single good thing
in this world,
then you spend
every penny.
It's a relief.
It'll help a lot.
[SIGHS]
Of course,
it's only a drop in the bucket.
I swear, everyone I know
has had problems with them.
I had one. The computer
in the engine,
it locked in the middle
of the Rockies.
Yeah, it decided I was
overheating and that was it.
Yeah. I couldn't
get it fixed for 100 miles.
I had to have it towed to
Telluride. It was unbelievable.
[BEEPS]
No.
No, it's the chip.
It's the little...
Yeah. It's, like, 800 bucks,
not counting labor...
Hey, Mel,
can I call you back?
Chuck, the Sandpiper
has landed.
Gentlemen,
I'm Jimmy McGill. Welcome.
Rich Schweikart. This is
Alvin Reese. Phil Jergens.
Thanks for coming.
Whoa, I have to ask you.
Please leave electronics
in the car.
Laptops, BlackBerries,
PalmPilots, watches.
If you lick it
and it goes bzzt, leave it here.
Why?
My brother Chuck
has a certain sensitivity.
It's a medical condition.
This is the price of admission.
Yeah, I heard about this.
Go ahead. It's fine.
[CHUCKLES]
There you go.
Make yourselves comfortable,
gentlemen. I'll be right back.
Chuck, come on, buddy.
I'm--
I don't know
if I can do this.
You can do this,
all right?
These guys--
Those guys,
they're nothing, okay?
They're the Pistons
and you're the Bulls.
All right? All you gotta do is
sit there and look intimidating.
They're scared of you already.
And they should be.
You're Charles McGill.
Let's go.
Let's go get 'em.
Oh. Hey.
Do you
remember me, Charles?
We were on a co-defense.
Church's Donuts v. Amendola?
It was, Jesus, nine,
ten years ago. Heh, yeah.
Our guys were suing
the other guys.
They were suing us
right back.
The city had some grievance
with everyone.
So we had to bundle, like,
four actions together.
I was sure that
we were sunk. But you...
You quoted-- What was it?
Huh? Addyston Pipe
and Steel.
You turned it all antitrust
and the whole thing went away
in summary judgment.
It was amazing.
I figured you'd be arguing
in front of
the Supreme Court someday.
Well, it's good to see you.
Yeah.
[CLEARS THROAT]
SCHWEIKART:
All right. Well,
let's get started. Um...
We've read
your revised demand.
It's quite a laundry list.
Very creative.
JIMMY:
Yeah, creative.
Like the way your clients
have been billing
my clients.
Because that's, like,
Salvador Dali creative.
Cute. You know, you're not
gonna make this stick.
Setting aside
evidentiary concerns--
Whoa.
You guys couldn't afford
10 bucks for a padlock?
That's on them.
Public property.
Maybe a judge sees that
your way. Maybe he doesn't.
But the damages
for elder abuse?
The statute requires proof that
there was some undue influence.
Someone threatening the
residents of Sandpiper Crossing.
No one has claimed
there was a guy with a knife
telling them
to hand over lunch money.
There are a lot of
assisted living facilities
out there
that may be disreputable.
But that's not the case
with our client.
All their facilities,
all 12 of them,
every single one,
five-star rated.
You go to any one
of them right now,
you'll see happy,
healthy residents.
Sandpiper takes care of these
people. They don't bilk them.
But we looked into it.
And some of your clients have,
in fact, been overbilled.
It's an accounting error.
It doesn't rise to the level
of fraud, not even close.
We've calculated the damages.
All told, it's $46,320.
Mm-hm. So here's what
we're prepared to do.
We're gonna
make your clients whole.
A check for the 46 and change
right now.
And on top of that,
we'll give you another
46K to cover your expenses.
So what's that, 92?
Let's call it $100,000 even.
We admit to no wrongdoing.
And your clients
release all claims.
[JIMMY SIGHS]
JIMMY:
I think you're gonna need
to do better than that.
SCHWEIKART:
This was in your demand letter.
They're syringes. So?
I don't know
if you know this, but that's
a standard item
in an assisted living facility.
Correct. It's not what
it is that matters.
It's where it's from.
Lincoln, Nebraska.
Go, Cornhuskers.
Since you're not picking up
what I'm putting down,
I'll explain it to you.
Nebraska, although they both
begin with the letter "N",
actually turns out to be a
different state than New Mexico.
So your client
accepted shipments
across state lines
for its enterprise.
In the U.S. mail, no less.
Are you trying
to make this a RICO case?
Like our client is
John Gotti or something?
You know as well as I do,
RICO's used mostly
for business beefs.
Sedima establishes
a pretty low threshold
for RICO provisions
to kick in.
Interstate commerce
is a bitch, huh?
Soon as we establish
a pattern to--
What was your word?
"Overbillings"?
I prefer
the classic term of "fraud."
You're looking
at treble damages,
so your 100 grand,
I think you know where
you can stick it.
Will you give us a moment?
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Well, what number exactly
did you have in mind?
Twenty million.
SCHWEIKART: Excuse me?
You heard me.
Oh, you can't expect--
CHUCK: Twenty million dollars.
Or we'll see you in court.
[CHUCKLES]
Hm.
JIMMY: Twenty million?
CHUCK: Didn't you hear them?
This is a big company.
Twelve separate facilities.
They can't possibly
all be in New Mexico.
This is
potentially a multi-state
federal class action lawsuit
with a RICO kicker
at the penalty phase.
Twenty million,
that's conservative.
Now, class cert,
that's where we start.
I'll draft our complaint.
Try to get us a conditional one.
They'll try to pierce it.
It should hold
long enough to start discovery.
We need to get you
back on the grounds.
Quash this prohibition
against you.
Some injunctive relief.
Maybe a TRO.
Jimmy, do you want to get
started on the TRO?
Yeah. Yes.
[DOGS BARKING]
[WHIMPERS]
It looks good.
No heartworm. No mange.
Where'd you get her?
Shelter.
Good. There's too many
puppy mills out there.
I had a dachsie
in the other day.
Some douche bred her
so much, poor thing.
She just had one giant hernia
for a belly. Couldn't even walk.
Those people can go straight
to hell as far as I'm concerned.
Anything else
I can do for you?
You still in touch
with your people?
Depends on the type
of work you're looking for.
Your do's, your don'ts
Your wills, your won'ts.
Well, you tell me what you got,
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I signed up three more clients
at the mall today.
Jesus, those mall walkers,
those geezers are faster
than you think.
I could sleep
for a decade.
Did you get what I asked?
The code provisions.
Oh...
Shit. Unh...
It's in the car.
Just give me a minute.
I'll, uh...
I'll go.
Where's the--?
Chuck?
Yeah?
[♪♪♪]