[♪♪♪]
[OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Everybody said
It was a shame ♪
♪ 'Cause her mama was working
On the chain gang ♪
♪ A mean, vicious woman ♪
Jesus.
It can't be done.
MAN:
You sure about that?
Ah. There's a trick, huh?
There's gotta be.
This guy wouldn't put money
on it unless there's a trick.
PIERCE:
I'm telling you,
it can't be done.
So you give up?
Yeah. All right.
Let's see it.
♪ Everybody said
It was a shame ♪
Oh, oh-- Wait, what?
No way.
Show me that again.
Sure. You got another 20?
Ahh.
Screw this.
MAN:
Ah, don't go away mad.
Oh, hey, guys.
You wanna buy a Rolex?
Whoa, whoa, hold on. How much
for that cheap piece of crap?
Look what the wind blew in.
Hey.
Holy crap. Jimmy, my man.
I said you would beat the rap.
Hey, Merna. Set him up.
No thanks. I'm good.
No, go on.
He don't mean it.
You just got out of jail.
Come on.
You're not gonna have a drink?
That'll be the day.
Settle down. I'm in a rush.
My brother's outside in a taxi.
The meter's running.
What, Chuck's outside?
Tell him to pull that broomstick
out of his ass and get in here.
No. We got no time.
We're catching a plane.
I came here to say goodbye.
I'm moving to Albuquerque,
New Mexico.
Mexico? You skip bail?
New Mexico. You know, like Bugs
Bunny and the Road Runner.
Okay, yeah.
What are you gonna do there?
I'm gonna work at his law firm,
like, in the mailroom.
To start, anyways.
Now you're talking crazy.
You just got out of jail.
Now you wanna go back?
Working for him,
that's all that is.
Marco.
I was done, you understand?
I didn't beat the rap.
Chuck flew in and saved my ass.
It's time to make some changes.
Hey. Listen to me.
You're Slippin' Jimmy.
What do you got to change, huh?
Everything.
It's time to grow up.
Yeah, according to who? Chuck?
The same goes for you, man.
You want to spend the rest
of your life on that stool?
I mean, come on, Marco.
Look at yourself.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
All right, that's him.
I gotta hit it.
Jeez. His master's voice.
Really?
Come on. Go outside.
Tell Chuckles that you got
some business you forgot.
Marco.
Come on.
You gotta have
one last blowout.
We'll do the watch thing again.
But maybe we'll pull
that tar-money scam
you were talking about.
Get some girls.
I made a promise.
Yeah, you made a promise.
But it was-- What do you
call it? --under duress.
Look, he got you out of jail,
okay? But he's your brother.
I mean,
what else is he gonna do?
Marco.
Listen to me, all right?
Chuck's not making me do this.
He's giving me an opportunity
and I'm grabbing it.
Gee, it's like watching
Miles Davis give up the trumpet.
What?
What does that even mean?
It's just a waste,
is all I'm saying.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Look, I'm gonna fly out there.
I'm gonna get settled.
And I'll call you, okay?
All right, Jimmy.
Hey, have a safe flight,
all right?
♪ My baby,
When she walks by ♪
♪ All the fellows go ooh ♪
♪ And I know why ♪
♪ It's simply because
That girl ♪
[♪♪♪]
Hey.
What's up?
Just waiting
to talk to Howard.
Can I ask about what?
I'm taking your advice.
I'm giving the case to HHM.
Why?
The fact that Chuck
doesn't want me here
has something to do with it.
I'm so sorry.
Why didn't you just tell me?
I just...
I didn't want you hating
your own brother.
HOWARD:
How'd you find out?
Did Kim tell you?
I figured it out
on my own.
It's about time, right?
I brought the Sandpiper stuff
with me. It's down in my car.
I figure your guys
could do the outreach.
If any of those geezers
don't wanna sign with you,
just give me their names,
I'll talk them into it.
You know, Jimmy, I never wanted
it to go this way.
If it had been up to me,
we would have--
Howard, I get it.
Your brother's very important
to the firm.
Sorry I called you
a pig fucker.
Well...
We owe you some money,
don't we?
The of-counsel fee.
I think we discussed 20,000.
That and whatever the
common-fund proceeds
of Sandpiper
ultimately adds up to,
you'll receive 20 percent
of that.
Should be a very nice payday
for you when it comes.
Yep.
I've got something
for you too.
It's a shopping list
for Chuck.
He's doing better, but he still
needs deliveries every day.
I think he'd be more comfortable
with someone else doing it.
I see.
You don't have to do it
personally.
It just needs to get done.
It's pretty straightforward.
The ice is a pain in the ass.
But he needs it.
I usually sneak into a motel
and fill a garbage bag.
But you can have whoever
you hire just buy it.
Most important thing
is the newspapers.
The New York Times. The Wall
Street Journal. They're a must.
There's a newsstand on Eubank
that has both of them at 6 a.m.
Which is good.
He's an early riser.
The Albuquerque Journal
gets delivered.
But somebody still has to
bring it in for him.
You've been doing all of this
every day?
For over a year?
You'll take care of this?
Absolutely.
I'll get it done and done right.
I always liked you, Jimmy.
Remember? I used to call you
Charlie Hustle.
Yeah, I remember that.
JIMMY:
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
That was nice.
You sure you're all right?
It's not a crime to let it out.
There's nothing to let out.
Chuck's a sick man.
That's no excuse.
He's my brother.
He thinks I'm a scumbag.
There's nothing I can do
to change that.
What else is there to say?
Wow, that's mature.
Dalai Lama's got
nothing on me.
[BALLS RATTLING]
O-64. As in
"Oh, to be 64 again."
O-64.
All right. Next up, we got N-32.
N as in "Nancy Reagan,"
First Lady with a lot of style.
Anybody else seen
Hellcats of the Navy?
All right.
No winners yet?
Okay. Here's B-2.
Just like the B-2 bomber,
the Stealth.
Probably one taking off
over at Kirtland right now.
We would never know
because it's stealthy.
Still no winners?
No?
Here we have
B-4. Another B.
How about that. As in:
"Before too long, we're gonna
have another winner."
No? Nobody? Okay.
All right. Ahem.
And here comes--
Hey, it's our old friend B.
Heh. B-12.
B as in, uh...
B as in...
"betrayal."
Benedict Arnold
betrayed the United States.
Still no winners?
No?
Okay.
Here it is.
Oh, what are the odds?
Four B's in a row. That's...
Heh.
B-7.
B as in...
"brother."
Brother.
B-7. Seven brides
for seven brothers.
I'm sure a lot of you
have brothers.
It's not like mine though.
Any winners yet? Take another
look, okay? I'll wait.
I'm gonna say if it's another B,
we could have
a real problem here.
And...
Hey, it is another B.
B-5, as in:
"Boy, this B thing is really
starting to tick me off."
B as in "battleship." B as
in "bourbon." B as in "Belize."
Beautiful place, so I've heard.
I would love to go there,
but let's face it,
that's never gonna happen.
None of us is ever leaving
this godforsaken wasteland.
Sorry.
Scratch that.
Moving on?
I mean,
what is it with this place?
It's like living
inside an Easy Bake Oven.
I mean, look out that window.
It's like a soulless,
radioactive Georgia O'Keeffe
hellscape out there,
crawling with coral snakes
and scorpions, and...
You ever see the movie
The Hills Have Eyes?
It's a documentary.
God forbid, your car breaks
down, you have to walk 10 steps.
You have melanoma
the size of a pineapple
where your head used to be.
So you ask, "Why?"
Why, if that's how I feel,
why do I live here? Why?
MAN:
Excuse me.
Are you gonna read that number?
Yeah.
I'm gonna read your number.
It's another B. Ha.
It's another freaking B.
Of course. Why not? Why not?
And the next number...
Quick question. Who here knows
what a Chicago Sunroof is?
Anybody? You, sir? No? Okay.
True story. Back home,
there was this guy named Chet.
Now, Chet was a real asshole.
He might have owed me
some money.
He might have slept with my wife
before she became my ex-wife.
The details don't matter.
Suffice it to say,
I was wronged.
All right.
So one summer evening,
I was out having a few drinks,
one or two, maybe three. Ha.
You get the picture.
And who do I see? Chet.
He drove up and he double-parked
outside a Dairy Queen
and went in to get some
soft serve. Now, Chet drove--
And this will give you an idea
of exactly what kind
of a douche bag this guy was.
Drove a white pearlescent
BMW 7 Series
with white leather interior.
Heh. So I saw that thing and
I had had a few, like I said.
And, uh...
I climbed up top
and I may have...
defecated, uh...
through the sunroof.
Not my finest hour,
I'll grant you that.
But that's what a Chicago
Sunroof is. Now you know. Heh.
It's a real thing.
I didn't make it up.
I'm not the first person to
do it. There's a name for it.
Guy wanted some soft serve,
I gave him some soft serve.
I did not know that his children
were in the backseat.
There was a level of tint
on the windows
that I'll maintain to this day
was not legal
in an Illinois licensed vehicle.
But somehow, that's on me,
I guess.
Who leaves two Cub Scouts
in a double-parked car
with the engine running?
Come on.
Now, Chet was connected, see?
Like Cicero, connected.
So usually I'd be looking
at malicious mischief,
public intoxication,
disorderly conduct, maybe.
But he's got the DA saying
indecent exposure.
Calling me a sex offender. What?
One little Chicago Sunroof,
and suddenly I'm Charles Manson?
And that's where it all went
off the rails.
I've been paying for it
ever since. That's why I'm here.
I don't...
You know what?
Any of this stuff you want,
come get it.
Kitty-cat notebooks
for everybody.
[MIC FEEDBACKS]
[♪♪♪]
♪ When I look out my window ♪
♪ There's so many
Sights to see ♪
♪ When I look out my window
Yeah ♪
♪ There's so many
People to be ♪
♪ It is strange ♪
♪ I think it's strange
Right now ♪
♪ You got to pick up
Every stitch ♪
What can I get you?
Old Style.
Make it two.
You got it.
What happened to Merna?
Merna?
She's doing all right.
She's my stepmom.
She don't come in
much anymore.
Tell her Slippin' Jimmy
says hello.
Slippin' Jimmy?
She'll know.
I'll tell her.
That'll be 5.50.
[JIMMY SIGHS]
Marco.
You gorgeous hunk of a man.
How long will you keep me
waiting?
Uhn. Wake up,
you fat son of a bitch.
Bought you a beer.
Jimmy?
In the flesh.
Come here.
Hey.
[BOTH LAUGH]
JIMMY:
So I'm not dark enough for you,
huh?
MARCO:
No, I'm just saying,
I don't see any color.
I mean, 10 years in a desert,
you should look like
Anthony Quinn
in Lawrence of Arabia.
"Turks, they paid me
in golden treasure."
BOTH:
"Yet, I am poor. Because I am
a river to my people."
Hey, I'm Irish, okay?
I spend my time
staying out of the sun.
Speaking of pale sons
of bitches,
how's your brother doing?
Chuck's fine.
Still working for him?
Sometimes.
What about you? I mean, besides
falling asleep on a bar
at 4:00 on a Wednesday
afternoon.
Lake Michigan Standpipe?
What's that?
My brother-in-law
owns the company.
Hold it. You got married?
No. No. No.
My sister Angie's husband.
So, what the hell's a standpipe?
You know what a standpipe is.
I don't think so.
The fire department comes.
Stick one end of the hose
on the hydrant,
the other on the standpipe.
Water goes out the standpipe,
through the sprinklers.
And then douses the flames.
It's important stuff.
So that's what a standpipe is,
huh?
Well,
it's a dry standpipe.
There's also the wet standpipe.
What's the difference?
I don't know if I could
explain it to a layman.
[COUGHING]
[GRUNTING]
Ahem. Excuse me.
How's your mom?
She passed away
about three years ago.
That's too bad.
A great lady.
Yeah.
From Wisconsin, right?
The funeral out there?
No, it was here.
Here?
Yeah, well, we were only
in town for a few days, so...
You're in town,
you didn't look me up?
Chuck was in the middle
of a big case.
And we couldn't stay around.
So...
BARTENDER:
Can I get you guys
anything else?
I'm good. Want anything?
Nuh-uh.
BARTENDER:
Your change here for you.
Hey.
Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
How's my Cutlass running?
Gets me around.
Well, it's a classic.
A little bodywork, a paint job,
really be something.
So, what you gonna do
while you're here?
I don't know.
See the sights, you know?
Catch a Cubbies game
from the bleachers.
Get a hot dog at Henry's.
MAN:
Mm-hm. Yeah. Uh-huh.
All right.
I'm gonna see them tomorrow.
Yeah, both of them.
Okay.
Okay. Bye.
Is he a regular?
No.
You're buying. I'm selling.
All right, then.
JIMMY:
All I'm asking
is that you take a look.
I'm sorry, buddy. No offense.
I'm just--
You know,
I'm not interested.
Come on, man.
What's it gonna hurt
to take a look?
It'll take you two seconds.
[SCOFFS]
All right. All right.
Show me what you got.
Boom.
Okay.
You see it?
I see a Kennedy half-dollar.
Which way is he facing?
JFK is facing left.
Exactly.
Which way is he supposed
to be facing?
Right. He's supposed
to be facing right.
Okay.
So why is this one facing left?
Heh. November 22nd, 1963.
Kennedy is assassinated,
right?
The whole nation
goes into mourning.
They start naming everything
in sight after him.
The mint wants in on the act.
So in '64, they decide to change
the Lincoln half-dollar
into the Kennedy half-dollar.
When they design it,
they put Kennedy facing right,
facing east.
Just the way they had Lincoln.
You know why?
East symbolizes the dawn.
That's why pretty much every
grave everywhere faces east.
You know, so the spirit of
the dead person faces the sun.
So that thing.
It's a burial thing.
But there's one technician
in the Denver mint, right?
This guy, he believed
in the New Frontier,
Camelot, the whole deal.
So the assassination,
it just destroyed him.
When he sees that coin
with Kennedy facing east,
facing the American past,
it pissed him off.
And so he went rogue.
Without telling anybody,
he flipped things around
so that Kennedy was facing west
towards the New Frontier,
the future.
Now, the mint struck
about 3000 of these
before they figured it out.
They canned the guy.
About 1000 of them made it out
into general circulation.
They managed to get most of them
back, melt them down.
But there's still 200 plus
floating around out there.
[CHUCKLES]
What's that?
I didn't catch that.
I didn't say anything.
You mind, buddy? We're having
a private conversation here.
This one's not in perfect
condition.
But on the open market, I'd say
it's worth 6 or 800 bucks.
Eight-hundred dollars?
Yeah.
I'm hard up so I'll take $100
for it.
You want me to give you
$100 for a half-dollar?
I want you to give me $100
for an $800 coin.
Yeah, I don't know, man.
I'm gonna go drain the snake.
Think about it.
[CHUCKLES]
This guy's playing me, right?
Definitely.
Slick son of a bitch.
You know, I should...
You know,
I know this guy on Wabash.
Coin dealer,
a friend of my uncle's.
Hey, Joey, can I use your phone?
Local call.
Keep it short.
Let's see.
I'm gonna call this guy.
When he tells me this is a scam,
know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna call the cops.
And get this scumbag
thrown in the can.
You're my witness, okay?
[♪♪♪]
Facing west.
My hairy ass.
Ahem. Hey.
How you doing? Yeah, it's Alvin,
Dave Tanner's nephew.
Yeah. Mm-hm.
Yeah. That's right.
Hey, this is gonna sound like
the beginning of a bad joke.
But I'm in this bar,
and I got this guy
spinning this cock-and-bull
story
about this 50-cent piece
he's trying to sell me.
He says... He says Kennedy's
supposed to be
facing west or something.
Yeah?
Yeah. Ahem.
Mm-hm.
AUTOMATED VOICE [OVER PHONE]:
At the tone,
the time will be 5:11 p.m.
Yeah.
That's what he said. Denver.
Jesus, no kidding?
Look. Listen. I gotta go.
All right.
Thank you.
Yeah, I owe you one.
Thanks, Joey.
So what'd he say?
Yeah,
he didn't really know much.
I'll tell you what.
I'll give you $50 for it.
Fifty dollars?
I'm taking a bath at $100.
All right. Okay. Look.
I got, like, $64 right here.
It's an $800 coin, okay?
I'm not gonna sell it to you
for $64.
If you wait for me,
I'll get you 100 bucks.
I don't know.
[WHISTLES]
Hey, buddy.
I got 75 bucks right here.
Hey, I-- Sorry.
I need a hundred.
Hey, slick,
nobody's talking to you.
Mind your own business, okay?
Come on.
Cash money, $80.
Look, if you give me a chance,
I'll be back with $100--
How long will that be?
I don't know. Catch a train.
Come back.
This guy was getting ready
to call the cops.
No, I was not.
Why would you?
This guy is making shit up.
Hey, I got 110 here.
Sold.
No, no, no.
This guy's got the cash.
Don't do that.
Take care of that.
It's history there.
Hey, you can't do that.
Money talks. You lost.
It's over.
No, it's not over.
That's crap.
Where do you think you're going?
Back off, dude.
I'll back off
when you give me the JFK back.
Call the cops. This guy
just tried to rip me off.
This guy's a liar.
I did not rip anybody off.
Yes, you did. You come back
in here, your ass is grass.
I got friends, buddy.
You hear me?
You double-dealing bastard.
I got friends!
[BOTH LAUGHING]
You are so beautiful.
Mwah! Ha!
Hey, everybody.
Next round's on us.
[♪♪♪]
All right. You listening?
Can you keep a secret?
Yeah. Absolutely.
Okay, his name is Idi Abbassi.
He's 27 years old.
He's a Nigerian prince.
He's worth, conservatively,
$400 million.
The dictatorship
of Equatorial Uqbar Orbis
is detaining him
on trumped-up charges.
Now, the Abbassi family,
they're going crazy.
They will reward whoever
helps them get their boy back.
The hitch is the banks
have frozen their--
--assets. I'm talking
Irish Sweeps tickets,
a whole trunk full of them.
They're just sitting at O'Hare,
impounded in customs.
Now, I know what you're saying,
"So what?"
I can leave this as security.
But you got to understand,
this violin is my livelihood.
It's a valuable antique.
What do you mean
it doesn't belong to you?
I'll pay 900 bucks for this.
Cash on the barrel.
MARCO:
I don't know.
I hate to part with it.
Been in my family for years.
JIMMY: You can keep a secret?
MAN: Yeah. Absolutely.
JIMMY: You need a good front.
So you're gonna have the
most return on your dollars.
But I know this customs officer.
Make it an investment.
If the price is right.
JIMMY:
I'm all about investments,
all about what's coming next.
Hey, kid,
help me get my wife's car
out of this bad neighborhood.
Sir, sir, could you help me?
Tell me,
are these today's numbers?
Now, none of this
was strictly legal, right?
And the import taxes
would have been a killer.
He had to find a way
to get money
into the country
without anyone knowing.
MARCO:
He coated the cash with this
black stuff, vectrol paste.
JIMMY:
And the only way to get it off
is with this special chemical.
MARCO:
It's not cheap, but the upside?
JIMMY:
The upside is huge.
Can you keep a secret?
You know,
the guy in Dances With Wolves?
[LAUGHS]
A guy like you,
who's got some money.
Got some money to throw around.
I know, "Who cares?"
No matter which one wins,
we're gonna get a piece.
He's got a gambling problem.
Nobody can come after you.
You get the profit.
The price is right.
It's a win-win for you.
It's a lose-lose
for everybody else.
You tell the guy
you've got a 14.
He checks, realizes...
Why we're getting a consortium.
It's just gonna be
a piece of the pie.
But you're gonna own a full
mountain range, guaranteed.
Can you keep--
A secret?
Because I really--
Really shouldn't--
Be telling you this.
[♪♪♪]
Hey.
JIMMY:
You are not Kevin Costner.
I was last night.
Jesus.
Asshole.
I mean, seriously?
Oh, Lucianne? Lucianne.
LUCIANNE: What?
WOMAN:
He's not Kevin Costner.
LUCIANNE:
What? So who's this guy?
WOMAN:
Not Kevin Costner's manager.
Come on. Let's go.
LUCIANNE: Okay, okay.
WOMAN:
Come on.
Get the hell out of this dump.
So are you sure
he's not a manager?
WOMAN:
Yes, Luci, I am sure.
He said he was gonna
give me his card.
WOMAN:
Does this look
like a manager's place?
Can I interest you ladies
in some mimosas?
At least stick around
long enough to get dressed.
Screw you.
If you build it, I will come.
Luci, come on.
Okay.
Bye.
WOMAN: Come on.
That door sticks.
Yeah, okay. I got it.
Okay.
Go. Go.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[SIGHS]
[PHONE BEEPS ON]
[DIALS]
AUTOMATED VOICE:
You have 15 messages.
GRETA:
This is Greta Muller. I wanted
to check to see if my will--
GARY:
My name's Gary Albert Arnold.
I'd like to discuss making a--
WOMAN 1:
Hi, Mr. McGill. I'm calling
on behalf of my mother.
She's in assisted living and--
[MARCO COUGHING]
MANNY:
Yes, Mr. McGill.
This is Manny Hollinger again.
WOMAN 2:
Hey, Mr. McGill.
So, what's it gonna be today,
pal?
I'm up for anything
and everything.
Marco, I'm sorry.
I gotta go back.
What?
It's been great. And I
appreciate your hospitality.
But a week's gonna have to
do it. I gotta go home.
I already called in sick.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on, man. This is home.
You hate it out there.
What do you got
to go back to?
My clients.
What clients?
What are you,
like a gigolo or something? Heh.
Uh, Marco. Ahem.
I'm a lawyer.
What?
Honest to God. I do elder law,
which is like wills and estates.
So you're ripping off
old people?
No, I'm not ripping off
old people.
I'm not ripping off anybody.
Holy crap.
Slippin' Jimmy's a lawyer?
[BOTH LAUGH]
No wonder you wanna go back.
I mean, you got to be
king of the desert.
Driving around town
in a white Caddy, making bank.
I'm not making bank. I'm making
a living, more or less.
A living? All due respect,
you're a lawyer
and you're not making bank,
you're doing it wrong.
I'm building something.
Takes time.
You're gonna build something,
build it here.
Lawyers in Chicago make plenty.
I don't know what to tell you,
Marco.
Chuck's in Albuquerque.
Again, all due respect,
Chuck's a stuck-up douche bag.
I hate to break it to you,
but he doesn't even like you.
He's my brother.
Okay. I get it.
Family. You gotta go back.
But...
Remember this?
The Rolex thing.
Whatever happened to the guy
who used to sell us those?
Jin Kang? He got deported.
This is the last one.
I say we go for it.
No.
Come on.
Last time, we did what, 600?
The hot streak we're on,
I bet we'd break a grand.
I could lend you some cash.
I don't need the money, Jimmy.
I need this.
Come on. You say you're happy
doing wills or whatever.
Good for you, man.
Seriously.
But I gotta tell you, standpipes
ain't cutting it for me, man.
I got nothing, Jimmy.
Give me this.
Give me this, man.
I can't do it.
Come on. Give me this.
Marco.
Give me this. Come on.
Listen to me.
I'm listening.
Hey.
One last time. Come on.
I'm not being hypnotized.
Okay. Come on. One more time.
I can't do it.
Just one more. One more.
Hey, listen to me.
I'm listening. Come on.
[EXHALES]
[MARCO HUMMING
"SMOKE ON THE WATER"]
[COUGHING]
[MEN HOWLING]
JIMMY:
Yeah.
It's gotta come from the gut.
KEVIN: Yeah.
JIMMY:
Yeah.
[JIMMY HOWLING]
KEVIN:
Oh, that's crazy.
JIMMY:
Just like a wolf. Go ahead.
[HOWLING]
No, deeper, deeper.
Yeah, and you do that
right at the moment of,
you know, pure joy.
Yeah.
And it will escalate it...
[HOWLS]
ten times. There's something--
Hey.
It's prehistoric.
Hey. Hey. Look.
[CHUCKLES]
Fifty, two-hundred,
four-hundred.
Whose is it?
I don't know.
There's gotta be 1000 bucks
in here. Somebody must have...
Oh.
Oh, damn.
Is he, uh...?
I don't know.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, buddy, you with us?
Look, the guy's just had
too many. I say we move on.
You wanna split this?
Marco, you okay?
Marco?
What, do you know this guy?
Hey, call 911.
Call 911.
Hey.
[♪♪♪]
I need an ambulance. My friend's
having a heart attack.
We're in an alley southeast
of LaSalle and Shermer.
No, I don't know. He was like
this when I found him.
Hey, hold. Marco?
Marco you with me? You with me?
I screwed up.
No, you did good, buddy.
Just hold on, all right?
They're on their way.
They'll be here in a minute.
Jimmy, you know what?
Save your breath.
You're gonna be fine.
This was the greatest week
of my life.
[LAUGHS]
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hang in there. Hey.
Hey, hey. Hey, wake up, man.
Come on. Marco, buddy.
[GRUNTING]
Help!
Anybody.
Marco.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, Jimmy.
Oh, hey, Bud.
Can I bum one?
Is that his?
Yeah.
His mom gave it to me.
I thought it looked familiar.
I figured I'd wear it today.
But I don't know.
I'm not a big ring guy, so...
Still. Could be worth
couple of bucks.
Better head back.
See you inside.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hey.
KIM: Is this Ferris Bueller?
Speaking.
Heh.
I don't want to interrupt
your big day off.
Just checking in.
What are you up to?
You know,
burning down the place.
I wouldn't expect any less.
So whatever it was, did you get
it out of your system?
Yep, all gone.
Good.
I want to run something by you.
The Sandpiper case,
it's getting too big for HHM.
Howard's decided to partner
with another firm.
Davis and Main,
you heard of them?
Sure, up in Santa Fe.
Right. Well,
they've heard of you too.
And they're interested.
They want to make an offer
contingent on an interview.
They've got a partner-track
position.
Wait. What? Partner track?
What are you talking about?
There's an office in Santa Fe
with your name on it.
Or there could be. And you'd be
working on your case.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, I-- I don't even, uh...
Chuck wouldn't like it.
Chuck has no say in this.
You wouldn't be working for HHM.
And Chuck can't tell
Davis and Main who to hire.
Why me? Is this like a tax
write-off or a charity thing?
What's the angle, huh?
Jimmy, we've been talking
to your clients,
the Sandpiper residents.
And they ask about you
every chance they get.
I don't know what it is,
but you have a way with them.
Hey. Old people love me.
So sounds good?
[CHUCKLES]
Kim, I can't imagine what
you did to make this happen.
Thank you.
I didn't do anything much.
And believe it or not,
Howard's been pushing this too.
Good old Howard.
Listen, we're gonna be down
in Judge Murray's court
on Thursday at 11.
The Davis and Main people
will be there.
It'd be the perfect chance
for you to meet them.
Thursday at 11. All right. I'll
be there. Thanks, Kim. Really.
I'll see you then.
CHUCK:
All the originals
need to be copied and filed.
See, I've written right here
on the box, "copy and file."
That's to make it
as clear as possible.
Got it, Mr. McGill.
Anything else?
Well,
on the grocery front,
almost everything
was right this time.
Great.
Almost.
It's a small thing,
but to my taste,
the Granny Smith apples
are a bit too tart.
Those are the green ones, right?
Right. I prefer the red ones.
But not Red Delicious.
Those are generally tasteless.
Fujis should be in season.
It's not a major issue, but...
Fuji apples. Okay.
Oh, and I'd like to try
soy milk.
So maybe a half gallon of that.
You got it.
Well,
thank you, Ernesto.
I appreciate your attention
to detail.
Do you need to write
any of this down?
Because it's okay if you do.
You know, just to be sure.
So Fuji apples.
Hey, Ernie.
Hey, how you doing, man?
Good. Good. So Howard's got you
looking after Chuck, huh?
Yeah. It's a few extra bucks,
you know?
How's he doing?
Seems okay,
like usual.
I'd say
we could grab a beer,
but they're waiting on paperwork
at the office.
You know how it is.
Don't I though? Heh.
See you, Jimmy.
See you around, Ernie.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CAR DEPARTING]
[♪♪♪]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CAR DEPARTING]
You done business
with him before?
[♪♪♪]
Right.
Yeah. I'll be there.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
Davis and Main and McGill. Heh.
Great to meet you. Ahem.
Nice to meet you, gentlemen.
It's good to meet you.
Nice.
MIKE:
Well, that was quick.
No charge.
Help me out here.
Did I dream it or did I have
$1,600,000 on my desk in cash?
When I close my eyes,
I can still see it.
It's burned into my retinas
like I was staring into the sun.
No one on God's green Earth
knew we had it.
We could have split it 50-50.
We could have gone home
with $800,000 each, tax free.
Your point being?
Why didn't we? What stopped us?
I remember you saying something
about doing the right thing.
I don't even know
what that means.
You want to know
why I didn't take that money?
Is that what
you're asking?
Yeah,
that's what I'm asking.
Me, personally, I was hired
to do a job. I did it.
That's as far as it goes.
Yeah.
Well, I know what stopped me.
And you know what?
It's never stopping me again.
[HUMMING
"SMOKE ON THE WATER"]
[♪♪♪]