[♪♪♪]
♪ Well, hello there ♪
♪ My, it's been a long, long time ♪
♪ How am I doing? ♪
♪ Oh, I guess that I'm doing fine ♪
♪ It's been so long now ♪
♪ And it seems that ♪
♪ It was only yesterday ♪
♪ Gee, ain't it funny ♪
♪ How time slips away ♪
♪ Gotta go now ♪
♪ I guess I'll see you around ♪
♪ Don't know when though ♪
♪ Never know ♪
Good night, ladies. Get home safe.
WOMAN 1: See you later.
WOMAN 2: Good night.
♪ But remember ♪
♪ What I tell you ♪
♪ That in time you're gonna pay ♪
♪ And it's surprising ♪
♪ How time slips away ♪♪
No, no. No!
No! Goddamn it! No.
Come on.
[GRUNTING]
Hey! Hey!
Somebody!
Hey!
[FAINT VOICE TALKING ON RADIO]
MAN [OVER RADIO]: --the problem with it
is because they believe he's worth....
[BANGING]
MAN 2:
--the problem of the National Football....
--the football from a player....
[BANGING]
--that took place. Those were attitudes....
--I mean,
there are plenty of rules in play....
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
You can go.
KIM:
Ah. Here he is.
HOWARD: Great. Jimmy, right on time.
Good to see you.
Hello, Howard.
-Hey. Hi.
-James McGill, Clifford Main.
Just Jimmy.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Clifford.
Likewise. We know all about
your work on Sandpiper.
JIMMY:
Well, it's a group effort.
I mean, the folks at HHM
are just knocking it out of the park.
-The case wouldn't exist without you.
-Absolutely.
Once you get him on your team,
you'll know why I call him Charlie Hustle.
Jimmy, these are my associates,
Brian Archuleta and Erin Brill.
-Nice to meet you both.
-Great to meet you.
I hate to do this....
...but could I borrow Ms. Wexler
for a moment?
-If you will excuse us....
-Ahem. Pardon me.
-What's going on?
-I just.... Ahem. Listen, here's the thing.
If I take this job,
does that mean the two of us...?
I mean....
-Does it mean...?
-What? What?
What the hell is this?
If I take this job today
with Davis & Main...
...does that mean that you and me...?
Is this-- Is this gonna happen?
Jimmy.
I....
[SIGHS]
One thing has absolutely nothing to do
with the other.
-Nothing at all?
-No.
Of course not, why would it?
Great.
Uh....
Sorry about that.
Listen, I just wanna say thank you,
sincerely, for your interest in me.
It's an honor to be considered,
but at this time-- At this time...
...I'm gonna have to take myself
out of the running. Thanks.
-Thank you, Howard.
HOWARD: Uh....
Jimmy?
MIKE:
Well, that was quick.
-No charge.
-Help me out here.
Did I dream it or did I have
$1,600,000 on my desk in cash?
No one on God's green earth
knew we had it.
We could've split it fifty-fifty.
We could've gone home
with $800,000 each...
...tax free.
Your point being?
Why didn't we?
I remember you saying something
about doing the right thing.
You wanna know why
I didn't take that money?
Is that what you're asking?
Yeah, that's what I'm asking.
Me personally, I was hired to do a job...
...I did it, that's as far as it goes.
Yeah, well...
...I know what stopped me.
And you know what?
It's never stopping me again.
[HUMMING]
JIMMY:
Chào các cô, ladies.
Mrs. Nguyen, it's a beautiful day out,
you should get out once in a while.
Throw a Frisbee, have some fun.
NGUYEN:
I have a business to run.
No, the business is running you.
Listen to me. You'll thank me later.
NGUYEN:
Cucumber water for customer only.
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
[CHATTERING STOPS]
[WOMAN GIGGLES]
[SPEAKS VIETNAMESE]
[HUMMING]
Hey, it's me.
Jesus. Hello?
Hello?
It's me. I got a new car. You like it?
We're not taking that to the meet.
How are we gonna get there?
I'll drive my car.
-Why?
-This business requires restraint.
That is the opposite of restraint.
But I like it.
I mean, I'm proud of it.
Good, then you be proud of it
on your own time.
But not with me, I'm not getting in that.
Okay, then don't.
Honestly, you don't really do anything.
I've been paying you
the salary of three people...
...to just stand behind me.
You know? And these last few deals,
this Nacho fella, he's been coming alone.
I mean, if he doesn't need backup men,
then, I mean, why do I need you?
I should just go alone.
I'm throwing-- I'm throwing away money.
Just tossing it away into the trash.
Look, you do whatever you want,
but I'm advising you...
...do not go to that meet
without someone watching your back.
Yeah, well,
of course you're gonna say that.
I mean, you don't wanna be
out of this easy-peasy job.
Well, I'm sorry,
but this is the gravy train...
...and it's leaving the station right now.
So last chance.
All aboard.
Seriously, last chance.
I'm gonna count to, say, 10,
and then I'm--
All right, then,
your services are no longer needed.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
No old guy?
What, did he break a hip
or something?
I know, right?
Yeah, no, we-- We parted ways.
Yeah, saw things differently, so....
You know how it is.
NACHO:
This is interesting.
Oh, yeah. You like it?
-Can I take a look?
-Oh, be my guest.
Get in, check it out.
Wow.
-Impressive.
-Thank you.
Get in, feel the leather.
Yeah, it's a H2.
Brand-new off the line.
Slimmer than the H1,
but longer, more height.
Yeah, it's a honey.
V8 engine, 325 horsepower.
Tri-zone climate controls,
so you can have a girl in a bikini...
...and another in a parka, and they're
both gonna be comfortable. Ha-ha.
You're riding around
with two girls in your SUV.
-You'd be really comfortable, huh?
-Oh, yeah. Yes.
I'm gonna count this quick.
Do your thing, make sure it's right.
Okey-dokey, we are good.
Same as before.
Still factory sealed.
And as always,
you're welcome to count them.
I trust you.
Great, thank you.
See you next time.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hello. Yes.
No, sorry.
Yes, this is James McGill,
but I'm no longer a lawyer, so....
That's right, not a lawyer. Bye.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
KIM: So this is what
a midlife crisis looks like?
Not midlife crisis.
Clarity. Midlife clarity.
Clarity? Huh.
Clearly explain to me why you walked out
on the best job opportunity of your life.
Get in the pool and I'll tell you.
-Get in the pool?
-Yeah, come on.
Pop in the gift shop and buy a bathing
suit. Get a one-piece, nothing fancy.
The water is perfect, it's 82 degrees.
You can order a drink,
and you gotta try this crab dip.
-Why are you acting like this?
-I'm not acting like anything.
I just finally decided to be me.
Everything okay, Mr. Cumpston?
Would you like another drink?
I'm good with this.
I'll tell you what, Mr. Cumpston.
If you really wanna talk,
I'll be in the bar. Not for long.
Hey, Rolando, check.
What do you--
What do you mean, "quit the law"?
I quit it, simple as that.
Oh, well, thanks for explaining,
Jimmy...
-...it's super clear now.
-Hey, buddy?
Is that a misprint right there?
It's gotta be, right?
-The Zafiro Añejo?
-Yeah.
-That's correct, believe it or not.
-Holy shit, a $50 shot of tequila?
-Is it worth it?
-Apparently.
It's kind of a personal choice thing.
Well, I can't die without trying
a $50 shot of tequila, so two.
Dos, neat, and we can charge that
to the room, can't we?
No, we can't. We....
I am paying.
And he will be having
a shot of your well brand...
...and I'll have a glass
of your house red.
We have a cabernet,
a pinot and a Syrah.
Whatever, dealer's choice.
-Something with alcohol.
-You got it.
Jimmy.
Did something happen in Cicero?
JIMMY:
Why did something have to happen?
KIM: When I talked to you about Davis
& Main, you were ready to take the job.
Now you're back,
and you're suddenly quitting the law?
Cheating hotels
out of expensive liquor.
Wearing a weird pinkie ring.
What, are you in the Mafia now?
Asking if we have a future.
I mean, where did that come from?
I don't know, I just....
Cicero has nothing to do with it.
It's my whole life. Well...
...my life since Chuck
made me come to Albuquerque.
Ever since I got here, all I've done
is try to make Chuck happy.
Bend over backwards to please Chuck.
Chuck, Chuck, Chuck. Well, no more.
You quitting the law,
isn't that exactly what Chuck wants?
Who cares? This is for me, okay?
I got into the law
for all the wrong reasons.
I'm trusting my instincts.
I think that my talents
are better spent elsewhere.
Where?
Floating in somebody else's pool?
[SCOFFS]
Jimmy, you're a great lawyer.
Why give that up?
I'm not saying it didn't have its moments.
But the stuff I liked about it,
selling people, convincing people...
...I don't have to be a lawyer to do that.
Besides, people tell me
how they see me...
-...and it's not as a lawyer.
WAITER: All right.
-Here you go.
KIM: Thank you.
WAITER: Let me know if I can
get you guys anything else.
MAN: Bobby, what up, brother-man?
KIM: Oh, thanks.
Short it.
Short it. Short that shit.
That stock is useless, it's got no legs.
It's like a circus freak minus the fun.
That one's even worse.
Who's giving you these?
Do me a favor. Take a pillow...
...put it over that stock's face
until you hear the deathbed queef.
-Okay, so?
MAN: It's a loser.
If you're not gonna be a lawyer,
then what?
Float around and wait
for your Sandpiper money to roll in?
-That could take years.
-Sandpiper has no bearing on this at all.
Okay, then, what's the plan?
-To be open to the universe.
-Okay, so no plan.
Just walk the earth?
Like Jules at the end of Pulp Fiction?
Look, whatever the universe presents,
whatever opportunity arises...
-...I will take it.
-Whatever opportunity?
-Yeah.
-Wasn't Davis & Main an opportunity?
It's a great opportunity,
and you're walking away from it.
Look...
...shouldn't you at least try the job
before you say no?
And waste everyone's time,
including my own?
Kim, I appreciate your concern...
...but it's not for me. I don't want it.
Jimmy, do you remember
how long you studied for that bar?
-How hard you worked?
MAN: It's like a burn victim....
All that effort,
you're just gonna toss it away?
That's the sunk cost fallacy.
-The what?
-The fallacy of sunk cost.
It's what gamblers do,
they throw good money after bad...
...thinking they can
turn their luck around.
It's like, "I've already spent
this much money...
...or time, whatever,
I gotta keep going!"
No, there's no reward
at the end of this game.
You are making a mistake.
I know you're making a mistake.
I've been doing the "right thing"
and where has it gotten me?
-Nowhere.
-I'm sorry, I don't....
MAN:
Yeah. Not my thing.
Not my thing. Still not my thing.
-I don't get it. I just don't get it.
-It's what's right for me.
MAN: Ha-ha-ha.
Donkey balls. Pure donkey balls, dude.
Wall Street's for suckers.
Who needs that aggravation?
If the Oracle doesn't have to live there,
I don't.
I can make a million-dollar stock trade
on my laptop sitting on a toilet.
Like Midas,
shitting gold bricks on my throne.
That's why Spiegelman and Deitch
want my business. I'm a golden god.
Of course I remember.
Who forgets that?
That fart had the anger
of a repressed minority community.
You fart like that in someone's face...
...you're gonna give them pinkeye
for life. Ha-ha-ha.
Good convo, bro.
Till next time, brother-man.
-Flip side, on it, check you.
-Come with me.
-What?
-Just come on, trust me.
What are you gonna do?
You wanna understand
what I'm talking about? Follow my lead.
Hey, buddy,
could you settle a bet for us?
-Can I what?
-Sorry...
...I don't want it to sound like
I was eavesdropping, but I kind of was.
We heard you talking about stocks.
-Uh-huh.
-Yeah, so question...
...if you could settle a debate
between me and my sister.
-We probably shouldn't bother--
-I wouldn't normally do this.
But we need an expert.
This guy sounds like he knows his stuff.
-Yeah, go.
-Okay, here's the question:
When it comes to the stock market,
is there a financial limit...
...to how much
a person's allowed to invest?
A limit?
No, no limit.
Knew it! Oh, even if it's an inheritance?
You know, with, like,
inheritance taxes and whatnot?
-Nope, same.
-That's-- Oh, fantastic.
Thank you, buddy. See, no limit.
Told you we could invest it all,
and it's a smart move, too.
-Sticking it all in the bank? No.
-Um....
Yeah, you can invest all your money,
just make sure you diversify.
Yeah, diversify.
That's-- We gotta-- Hey...
...what do you mean "diversify"?
Well, diversify is-- You know the saying
"don't put all your eggs in one basket"?
-Right? Same principle.
-Makes complete sense. Thank you.
If I had an idea of the money
we're talking about, ballpark...
...I could give you examples
of smart diversification.
Yeah, um....
Look, an uncle on our father's side
recently passed...
...and he left us somewhere
in the neighborhood of 1.4 million.
And I don't mean to be greedy,
but I think if we invest it smart now...
...we could double it, triple it...
...we could quadruple
the whole inheritance, right?
In my opinion?
Fortune favors the bold, man.
If you're free to join me for a drink,
I can give you a consult.
That's all right, we'll do it ourselves
through an online brokerage site.
We're just gonna pick classic-- Like,
I think they're called blue chip stocks.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You can totally do it yourself.
Shoot for the tried and true.
Of course, you might be putting your
cash in the Hindenburg, Andrea Doria...
...Corky Romano.
Right? They all seemed
rock solid beforehand. But then....
-Yeah, not good.
-Not good, yeah.
So how do you know?
Well, that's where
someone like myself comes in.
Proven track record as a wealth manager.
I take calculated but aggressive risks...
...because I wanna catch lightning,
and I do.
-I'm practically a money-printing machine.
-That sounds good.
A money-printing machine.
Listen, there's a little booth over here,
there's some privacy, we can talk.
No obligations,
we can just rap about this a little bit.
-Yeah, I guess.
-Yeah?
What do you say, sis?
Can we just talk?
Electric slide on in there.
We'll rap a little, it's no--
-My name's Ken, by the way.
-Viktor, with a K.
Cool, Viktor with a K.
And this lovely lady is?
It's Giselle.
-Giselle Saint Claire.
KEN: Ah. Lovely.
Please, sit. I won't bite.
So Viktor with a K and Giselle,
exotic names.
-They're Dutch.
-Well, Boer to be precise.
Our father's side of the family
is from South Africa...
...which is where Uncle Humphrey
passed away.
South Africa, they grow them beautiful
down there, right? Charlize Theron.
-And you.
-Oh, well.
I've never actually been,
but hope to go someday.
Tell you what,
when I'm done with you...
-...you might take your own private jet.
-Nice.
Excuse me, hi. We are sitting here now.
We could use a wine list
if you get a chance--
Hey, are you a tequila fan?
Yes. You down for that?
You ever try Zafiro Añejo?
No, I have not, but I'm down for whatever.
Three of whatever she just said.
-You got it.
-All right.
So stock market, a great investment...
...and you're picking the right time
to jump in.
JIMMY:
Why do you listen to him? He's an idiot.
He talks about his cars. He talks about...
KEN: How many cars did he have?
KIM: I don't think....
[JIMMY AND KIM LAUGH]
KIM: It makes sense.
JIMMY: That's it, Ken.
Oh, yeah.
Compliments of the bartender.
Thought you might want a souvenir.
-My God, did we drink the entire bottle?
-Not yet, we didn't.
Right here. Hey, hey, cheers.
I think we're ready for the check.
[COUGHS]
Oh....
No, really, it's a smart way to go.
Okay, but, so to be clear...
...you take the money
directly from our account...
-...and invest it--
-Diversify it.
Diversify it. And then all the dividends
and all the profits...
...and the what-have-you
comes back into our account.
Boom. Absolutely.
You'll get a statement showing
how much your money is growing...
-...biggest bulls of the month, etcetera.
-Ken, buddy...
...let's do this.
Great.
Right there, Viktor with a K.
And, Giselle, you are next.
-This is so exciting.
KEN: Mm-hm.
WAITER: Folks, it's been a pleasure.
-Oops. I got that.
-Can't let you do it, son.
JIMMY: Wait, what? Ken.
-You are the greatest. Thank you.
-No problemo.
This will be the best decision
you'll make.
JIMMY:
We should get out of your hair.
KIM: Yeah.
-Wait, wait, wait, this...
...is for you.
Now, that's got all my contact info.
Call me anytime with questions,
or anything at all.
-Ken.
-Bye.
Call me, guys.
-Try and stop us.
[KEN CHUCKLES]
Wow. Heh.
Just wow.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey.
What--?
-Is this right?
-Yes, sir, it is.
KIM:
Go, go, go!
[LAUGHING]
-Zafiro Añejo!
-Shh!
Shut up. He's gonna come out.
-Oh, no, I didn't read the fine print.
-Wait!
Yeah!
[LAUGHING]
KIM: Holy crap.
-I can't--
[EXHALES]
[LAUGHS]
JIMMY:
Can I borrow that when you're done?
No, that's gross.
How is it gross?
Our germs have already intermingled.
It's my toothbrush, it's different.
-Why is it different?
-Because.
You know, gums bleed,
and there's cold sores....
All sorts of food and weird--
-Come on.
-What? No!
-Come on, I'll do it right now.
-I don't care.
-I need to brush my teeth.
-I don't have an extra.
That's fine. I got this.
-Good, I'm fine with it.
-Yeah, me too.
Wait till you see what I floss with.
[KIM LAUGHS]
That's a keeper.
Thank you, Viktor with a K.
Hey, wouldn't it be great
if we could do that every night?
Yes, it would.
But we can't.
I know. Yeah.
But I'm just saying,
if we could it would be great.
But I know we can't.
Oh, crap, I can't be late today.
Howard is doling out assignments...
...and the last one through the door
could get stuck in Doc Review.
You got somewhere to go?
Yeah. Yeah, I got somewhere.
You good?
JIMMY:
Yeah, all good.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Daniel Wormald.
I'm Officer Baker, this is Officer Saxton.
Yeah, please, come on in.
Come in, it's over here.
See what they did?
I mean, all gone. All of them.
-Just--
-What's all gone?
I have-- I had a baseball card collection.
-A major collection, all stolen.
-Sorry to hear that.
Was it common knowledge
that you have baseball cards?
No, not really.
So nobody in particular
you can think of wanted them?
No, not that I-- No.
-How'd they get in?
-The back door over here.
It was open
when I came home for lunch.
I mean, it was locked...
...but they must have jimmied it open
or something.
Uh-huh.
What time you figure this happened?
DANIEL: I left for work at 8:15,
came home for lunch at 12:30...
-...and called you immediately.
-Was anything else taken?
DANIEL: Cash, a fair bit.
-How much cash?
Uh, I don't know. You know, let's focus
on what's important here.
You know, all I really care about
are my baseball cards.
I have a Topps Mickey Mantle
rookie card that's irreplaceable.
It's a mint, 60-40, 90-10 on the reverse.
I can go on.
All my cards are in top-loaders...
...but if they're taken out
and exposed to the elements...
...I mean, or creased, God forbid...
...I mean, you're looking at a 9-point
downgrade in a matter of seconds.
I understand the first 48 hours are most
important in investigations like this....
...so the more time passes, I mean,
the less likely we are of a recovery.
So time is of the essence here, guys.
Well, we're gonna help you out
the best we can, Mr. Wormald.
Good.
Ugh. They really tossed this place.
Are you sure they weren't looking
for anything else?
-Like what?
-I don't know.
Just wondering your thoughts.
I assume more baseball cards.
Did you have more
than the ones in the case here?
Yes, in back. Thousands.
But these were the crown jewels
over here.
You know, the all-star lineup.
Right.
Hm.
-What?
-Just trying to make sense of it.
DANIEL:
What's to make sense of?
I mean, isn't it as simple as the perp
was looking for more baseball cards?
Or hopped up on speed or whatever
and went nuts with the vandalism?
Yeah. I mean, that could be, yeah.
Pretty sweet Hummer
parked in the driveway. That yours?
Yeah, that's mine. It's a lease.
Got a great deal on it.
It's very sweet.
They say Arnold Schwarzenegger's
the reason that Hummers exist.
-Don't know how, but that's what they say.
-No kidding?
Huh.
What kind of work do you do,
Mr. Wormald?
I work IT...
...for a pharmaceutical company.
Wow, computers.
God, I should've gotten into computers.
-I'd have that same Hummer.
-Right.
Look, guys, I'm glad you like my car...
...but I think we're looking through
the wrong end of the telescope here.
-The priority is my baseball cards.
-Of course.
Yes, now, I have a detailed manifest
of my entire collection...
...and asterisks next to
the high-ticket items.
It's clear which ones
they'll try to fence first...
...because they're
super, super valuable.
So you're gonna wanna get this list
out to pawn shops, collectors.
Question anyone who's done
any sort of crime like this in the past.
You know, the usual suspects.
Can I get you the list
so you can start investigating?
-Yeah, if you could get us that list....
-Okay, I'll print it out.
Hank Aaron, mint.
God, my signed Derek Jeter.
Willy Mays, O-Pee-Chee.
Gotta breathe.
Just keep breathing, keep breathing.
-Okay.
-I know, right?
-Left the TV...
-Uh-huh.
-...left the computer.
-Right.
Huh.
There's something wrong
with this picture.
[SIGHS]
[PHONE DIALING]
Hey, it's me.
Another perfect day in paradise out here.
I'm in the pool.
Okay, call me.
WOMAN: Hi, how are you?
MAN: Hey, babe, did you get lunch?
WOMAN:
I did.
MAN: I think I'm burning up back here.
-Oh, really?
-You're just in luck. Look what I have.
-Oh, hey, great.
WOMAN: You're all red back here.
-Yeah.
I feel stupid.
[PHONE DIALING]
WOMAN: I told you not to spend
so much time in the sun.
You don't listen.
Yeah, it's me again.
Listen, as I speak,
not 25 feet away from me...
...I'm looking at the mark.
Think Thurston Howell III
if he shacked up with Ginger.
He's dripping in Gucci.
It's like I'm at the watering hole...
...and I'm watching the fattest,
slowest water buffalo...
...expose his neck to me,
and I'm the lioness ready to strike.
[CHUCKLES]
Come, Kim, join me.
Join the pride.
I said "lioness" because it's the females
who do all the hunting.
I just wanted to be species-accurate...
...irrespective of my own sex,
it's a National Geographic thing.
Anyway...
...get out here.
Bye.
[PHONE BEEPS]
[SIGHS]
[DIALING]
Santa Fe, New Mexico.
I need the number of a law firm,
Davis & Main.
Yeah, you can connect me.
[♪♪♪]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
MAN: There are a few options
on the company cars.
We can arrange a test drive
whenever you'd like.
Company car, wow.
And there's a service that will deliver it
right to you, wherever you want.
And if you find you're not happy with it,
it's not a big deal to change it out.
That sounds really, uh....
Yeah.
This is interesting.
Oh, if this isn't to your taste...
...we have a collection of art in-house
you can choose from.
Any time you're ready, I can put together
some samples for you to review.
I-- I-- I like this.
Good. Well, any other needs you have,
I'm here to help.
Office supplies, dietary needs.
Anything special
you want stocked in the fridge?
Maybe a humidifier?
-Gets kind of dry in here.
-Omar, I'm pretty low maintenance.
Sure. Well, if there's anything you need,
I'm right outside the door.
-Great. If I think of anything.
-Okay.
Hey, do you think...?
I'm just looking at this.
Do we get a choice of desks?
What were you thinking?
Is it possible...?
Can we do a cocobolo?
Cocobolo desk?
Absolutely. I'll get right on that.
[CHUCKLES]
[♪♪♪]