[♪♪♪]
[EXHALES]
WOMAN [OVER TV]: My husband and I
scrimped and saved for so many years.
We did our best to build a nest-egg...
...so that we wouldn't be
a burden to our family.
After Ronald passed, I moved
to an assisted living facility.
A nice place.
They told me
they'd take care of everything...
...but then one day they said
all my money was gone.
How could that be?
Where did it all go?
JIMMY: If you or a loved one is a resident
of a Sandpiper Crossing facility...
-...or associated retirement....
-Jesus. You used your own voice?
Strictly to save money.
-All in, the whole thing cost--
-Just.
Call the law offices
of Davis & Main...
...at 505-242-7700.
That's 505-242-7700.
Production cost: $647, all in.
The one single airing
was a $700 ad buy, so dirt cheap.
CLIFF: You think this is about money?
That's what this is about?
I'm just trying to offer
complete information, here.
Now, this one airing, it was an experiment
and as such, by any measure...
-...a success.
-You keep saying experiment...
...like you're
the goddamn Wright Brothers.
When were you going to tell us
about this experiment?
Today. This morning.
I admit I got a little ahead of myself.
A little exuberant...
...and for that, I apologize.
But the headline here is, I think...
...we've gotten nearly 200 phone calls
since this one airing.
Cliff, since you and I spoke last night,
72 more.
[PHONE RINGING OUTSIDE]
And you hear that? Right there.
-That's the sound of victory.
-Jimmy, stop selling.
And don't act like
you don't see the problem here.
-I don't.
WOMAN: You cut us out.
-You did an end run around us.
-Exuberance is no excuse.
Cliff...
...client outreach is my department.
You told me that day one.
If you're in charge of payroll...
...would I be okay with you giving
million dollar bonuses?
You and I did discuss the possibility
of a commercial.
The possibility in the abstract...
...for a grand total of 30 seconds
when I was halfway out the door.
I guess-- I thought I heard enthusiasm.
So I-- I took some initiative.
Some? Wow.
We are a team at Davis & Main.
This is a team approach.
You coming as a solo practitioner,
I knew there's gonna be a learning curve.
But if you simply can't fit in
as part of the team--
I can fit in. I-- I fit in.
I am here to help you and HHM...
...win Sandpiper.
That's all this was about.
Sandpiper's not what keeps the lights on
around here.
We have clients who wouldn't want
to be associated with this kind of-- This.
Our image, our reputation...
...is something we've been
carefully building for years.
It's worth far more than any one case.
Something like this could damage it.
Suffice to say, there's not a lot of love
for you in the room at the moment.
The vote is currently 2-to-1 to fire you
for cause.
However...
...I believe in second chances.
But know this is both strike one
and strike two.
Going forward, you can expect
a great deal more scrutiny.
[PHONES RINGING]
WOMAN:
Yes, ma'am, let me take your number.
[BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
Come on, come on.
KIM [ON RECORDING]: Hello, you've
reached the voicemail of Kim Wexler.
Please leave me a message and I'll
get back to you as soon as I can.
Hey, Kim, I need you to call me
as soon as you can, all right?
It's a time-sensitive thing, so, uh....
I mean, I may have, uh....
Just... Well, please call me
before you talk to Howard, okay? Bye.
[PHONE BUZZES]
HOWARD: It's a simple question. Did you
or didn't you know about this commercial?
KIM:
I-- Yes.
-He showed it to me--
-He showed it to you?
-Yes. A few days ago.
-And you didn't say anything to anyone?
No. I didn't.
-You didn't think I deserved a heads up?
-I didn't realize--
At the time,
I didn't think it was necessary.
You were wrong about that.
We were caught flat-footed
in front of our co-counsel.
Which, I don't need to tell you,
does not reflect well on HHM.
Or on you.
That'll be all.
You can go.
What are you going to do?
[SIGHS]
NACHO:
So, what do you think?
I figure from here,
you got a good bead on the place.
But someone inside,
they can't pick you out.
Tuco and me, that's our spot.
He always sits facing out.
Looks like a gangster thing, but
it's so he can keep an eye on his ride.
Every Tuesday, we're here
squaring accounts...
...dealer comes in, pays what he owes.
Tuco, he likes to get face-to-face.
Says everything he needs to know
is right here.
Looks them in the eyes. Just stares.
Like he's looking inside of them.
I seen him go like that five, ten minutes.
MIKE:
And what does that accomplish?
He calls it his lie detector.
That's why these things go all day.
Just the two of you? No extra muscle?
NACHO: Don't need it.
We can handle our business.
Anyway, it takes hours.
Collect the cash. Count it. Lie detector.
One at a time. Guy comes in,
transacts, then the next.
Then, when we're done,
Tuco gets in his car...
...I get in mine, boom,
we go our separate ways.
That is where you come in.
See him packing up,
drive over.
Pull up in the spot next to Tuco's,
pop, headshot, roll out.
Easy.
I-40 on ramp is eight blocks up.
You're in the wind before anyone
has time to blink. And here's the beauty.
All these dealers?
They know we're here.
So the story is...
...one of them got ideas, decided
to kill Tuco, get a cut of the business.
Could've been any of them
as far as the cartel's concerned.
These Tuesdays of yours.
Day or night when you wrap it up?
NACHO: Day.
-So full daylight, plenty of traffic.
How exactly do I not get seen?
My car, at least.
Murphy's Law tells me
somebody's gonna pull the plate.
NACHO:
Fine. Go to the yard, buy a beater.
You gotta stay in the car.
[WHISTLES]
Ain't no one gonna see you.
If they do see you, so what?
That's why you're perfect.
You're no one, you got no connections.
-You're a ghost.
-Mm.
So I pull in next to him.
That assumes there's a parking spot.
Our guys park next to him.
They come and go from the same spot.
Last one takes off, you're open.
Someone comes in behind me,
I'm blocked.
-Who's gonna pull in behind you?
-I'm guessing someone who likes tacos.
What then? What's my exit?
NACHO:
I don't know. Get out and run.
MIKE:
Bad knees.
Look. The details?
That's what I'm paying you for.
You got a better plan? Go on. Tell me.
I'm all ears.
You sure about this?
Killing your partner, heh...
...that's a bell you don't unring.
See this?
You know how I got this?
Back in '96, '97,
Tuco and I were working...
...with these bikers out
of Riverside County.
They were running
this peanut-butter crank.
Real shit, you know, but cheap.
We could sell it as fast as we got it.
Anyway, Tuco develops a taste for it...
...and crank does not bring out the best
in people, made Tuco erratic.
Our connect was a guy
called Dog Paulson.
One day, Tuco's settling up with Dog,
he decides to put on his lie detector.
Dog is like, "What the hell," you know.
Tuco just keeps staring at him,
then he goes real quiet.
"You think I'm an idiot, Dog?"
He thinks Dog
is supplying his competitor...
...trying to cut Tuco out.
Dog, he denies it.
"No way, not me."
Tuco doesn't even raise his voice,
but suddenly he's got a sawed-off...
...and right in Dog's face.
I was behind him.
Sickest thing I ever saw to this day,
and this...
...a piece of Dog's skull under the skin,
a little piece of him.
Tried digging it out,
but it's in there pretty good.
Not the kind of thing
you go to the doctors for.
The thing about it
was Tuco really liked Dog.
Kind of felt bad afterwards.
But when he's using:
[POPS]
Loco, crazy.
There's no other way to put it.
And he's using again, crystal,
much bigger kick.
So it's like you said, if Tuco finds out
about my independent ventures...
...it's gonna be Dog all over again.
It's him or me.
There.
Man with a scoped rifle
could get a clean shot.
Fire a single round, disappear before
anybody knew what had happened.
No witnesses, clean egress.
Pretty far.
You can make that shot?
Yeah.
You saying you'd do it?
Fifty grand.
I'll look into it.
-Hey, uh...
-Your brother isn't here, Mr. McGill.
I know. He sent me to get his ink blotter.
I'll just be a second.
-Watch yourself, the floor is slick.
-Thank you, Gesualdo.
Sorry about the floor.
Oh, no.
Are you looking for Miss Wexler?
-Guess I'm too late, huh?
-No, she's still here.
Where?
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Kim.
I am so, so sorry.
-I should've told you last night.
-You think?
I honestly thought I could fix it.
I thought they'd understand
once they saw the numbers.
I knew it would work, and it did.
It worked.
Howard can't just stick you in Doc Review
because of something I did.
Plus, at an entirely different law firm.
What kind of sense does that make?
I told you this would happen.
-He can't blame you for this.
-I warned you he would.
I'm talking to Howard.
What, call him a "pig fucker" again?
Yeah, that will help.
I screwed up, you know. I know that.
But this, this is total BS.
I'm talking to him tonight.
-Jimmy, no. It'll only make things worse.
-I'll explain it to him.
No.
I'm not asking you, I'm telling you.
If you go to Howard,
you and I, we're done.
So we're not done now?
I need this job.
And there's a weekly billing quota
that I'm about 40 hours behind on...
...so could you please just go?
I'm sorry.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
JIMMY:
Chuck.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Chuck!
Come on!
I'm not going away.
All right, you asked for it.
[DOORKNOB JIGGLING]
I'm coming in.
[CHUCK GROANING]
Chuck?
Chuck.
[GROANING]
Can you hear me?
Can you talk to me?
-You want me to get you to the hospital?
-No. No hospitals.
I'll be all right.
Get some water, please.
Extra protection here.
[GROANS]
Here. You know what? Sit up.
-Can you sit--?
-Ah, ah. All right.
Okay, all right. Here.
Ah. Hmm.
Hm.
[SIGHS]
MAN:
That's the Armalite AR-50.
State-of-the-art,
accurate to 2400 meters.
I got the Leupold Mark 4 on it now...
...but I can always upgrade it
to a Schmidt & Bender.
Single-shot, bolt.
Simple, effective, reliable.
It fires a .50 caliber BMG.
Very effective against soft targets...
...in light cover, behind cars,
small-diameter trees and such.
As always, I've gone to the trouble
of grinding down the serial number.
No, unless you ground the hole
clean through, acid will recover it.
Well, that would be true,
but I follow up with a pass...
...through a random
stipple machine press.
Hides the patterns and metal density.
Should throw off your X-ray diffraction
and some other higher-end methods.
Nothing's perfect, of course,
but this is close.
Mm. Looks like a hernia
with a scope on it.
Thirty-four pounds, not including
your bipod, which adds some heft.
Too much gun.
For most applications,
I would tend to agree.
SR-25 Match rifle.
Eugene Stoner-designed semi-auto.
That's about 11 pounds there.
Not quite the range or the punch
of the AR-50...
...but you're talking about a .5 MOA
at well past a thousand meters.
-I've heard they're prone to jam.
-It's been known to happen in the field...
...but there's not a semi-auto built
can boast it never jams.
If that's a concern,
you ought to stick to bolts.
Good bolt-action rifle, if you jammed it,
I'd wager you were setting out to do so.
Which brings us to the M40.
Tried and true, battle-tested.
Essentially the same rifle used
by Marine snipers since 1966.
It's light, accurate, good for soft
targets in the 8- to 1200-meter range.
You seem to know this one.
Oh, yeah.
You could say that.
That's the A1 model. There's not much
change from the original.
Biggest difference is the stock.
It's fiberglass instead of wood.
-They changed it over in 1970 or so.
-Good.
Wood warped like hell.
You get it wet,
put it in the sun, gone.
Somebody probably should have
figured that out...
...before they sent it into
a damn jungle.
Yeah. Probably.
If these aren't to your liking,
I could get my hands on a few more.
No. I've changed my mind.
Thank you.
I don't need anything at this time.
-For your trouble.
-No, it's no trouble.
I make my living
on repeat business.
When you need what I'm offering,
you know how to find me.
[SIGHS]
You're still here.
-Yeah, I'm still here.
-Hmm.
[CHUCK GRUNTING]
Did you get any sleep?
Some.
Enough.
How you feeling?
I could use some tea.
Thanks.
[BOTH SIGH]
-You scared me last night.
-Yeah.
Happens sometimes.
Sometimes I overdo it, that's all.
It passes.
Going into the office really takes it
out of you, doesn't it?
If I stay too long, yeah.
Guess it's hard not to stay.
There's so many important things
for you to do there...
...like, you know,
stick it to Kim Wexler.
What did I do to Kim Wexler?
She's back in the cornfield,
isn't she?
I didn't do anything to Kim.
I mean, I was present, yes...
...but management of personnel,
those decisions are all Howard's.
That is rich. Now, tell me, when Howard
was making his management decisions...
...was he sitting on your knee,
with your arm up his ass?
Hey, can he talk
while you drink a glass of water?
That's uncalled for.
And if Howard were my puppet...
...he certainly wouldn't have
recommended you to Davis & Main.
Actually, I'm sure it was Kim Wexler
who talked him into doing that.
-Hence his anger.
-Don't punish Kim.
If you're mad at me,
take it out on me.
[CHUCK CLEARS THROAT]
I know you like to think the world
revolves around you...
...but this has nothing
to do with you.
Kim had a responsibility
to Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
She should have been looking out
for her firm's interests.
Not letting us know
what you were up to was her mistake.
Oh, come on. You can't be
pissed off at her about this.
I'm not. Howard is.
-And why shouldn't he be?
-Because she didn't know.
She didn't know I was gonna
air the commercial.
She didn't know I hadn't gotten
it approved. She--
She didn't know.
-I see.
-She didn't know there was anything...
...she was supposed to tell Howard.
As far as she was concerned,
Cliff Main was already looped in.
You told her he was?
I implied it. So it's on me.
Not her.
She didn't say anything to us
about that.
She wouldn't. No,
she wouldn't want to make me look bad.
You have to admit this shows
a lack of judgment on her part.
She knows you.
She should have known better.
-You are such an asshole.
-Why?
For pointing out her one mistake
was believing in you?
Chrissake, can we get
some perspective here?
It was a simple little commercial.
It aired once, that's all.
Can I remind you, it worked?
It worked like a dream.
See, that's your problem, Jimmy.
Thinking the ends justify the means.
And you're forever shocked
when it blows up in your face.
What did I do
that was so wrong?
You broke the rules.
You turned Kim
into your accessory.
You embarrassed Howard, who--
God help him.
--inexplicably vouched for you
with Cliff Main.
You made Cliff and his partners
look like schmucks. Shall I go on?
How he hasn't fired you for this
positively mystifies me.
Perspective.
You want perspective?
I'll give you mine.
You're my brother,
and I love you...
...but you're like an alcoholic who
refuses to admit he's got a problem.
Now someone's given you the keys
to the school bus...
...and I'm not gonna let you
drive it off a cliff.
Can we just get down
to brass tacks here?
What can I do to put Kim back
where she belongs, huh?
You want me to quit Davis & Main?
That's fine!
I never wanted that job
in the first place.
I can't get through to you. Life is not
one big game of Let's Make A Deal.
Yes, it is. I'm Monty Hall.
What's behind door number two?
What'll it take? Huh?
You want me to quit
being a lawyer?
Yeah. A chimp with a machine gun,
that's me, right?
Huh? So? What do you say?
You help Kim, I quit the law.
-Is that a deal?
-I didn't say that.
You didn't say it,
but that's what you want, right?
That's why you put the screws to Kim,
to squeeze me!
I didn't say that
and I would never say that.
-Why not?
-Because if I were impeding the career...
...of one of my employees, compelling
you to do something against your will...
-...that would be extortion.
-Yeah. It would.
So? You gonna extort me, Chuck?
It's a lead pipe cinch you get away
with it. I'm not gonna tell anyone.
It's real easy.
You just set things right for Kim.
You get her back in her office,
out of Doc Review, back to normal...
...and I quit the law for good.
No more Jimmy McGill, esquire. Poof.
Like he never even existed.
Wow. Wow.
But I need to hear the words
come out of your mouth.
You're a man of your word.
You're an upstanding man, right?
-God's sake, Jimmy.
-Come on, Chuck! Extort me!
Say "quit" and I will quit, but I need
to hear it from your mouth.
You want me to commit a felony.
Because that's
what you'd do, right?
You wanna believe that deep down,
I'm some hypocrite.
Let's find out.
Come on down, Chuck...
...roll around in the dirt with me.
All your dreams will come true.
Go on, do it! Go on!
I am not the bad guy here.
You don't wanna be a lawyer, that's
between you and the New Mexico Bar.
You wanna quit Davis & Main,
be my guest.
You don't need help from me
to tank your career.
You're doing just fine
on your own.
Speaking of which,
it's an hour's drive to Santa Fe.
Even if you leave right now...
...you're still gonna be
at least 20 minutes late for work.
Another feather in your cap
with Clifford Main.
NACHO:
So?
MIKE:
I'm not gonna do it.
Are you negotiating now?
No amount of money
makes this a good idea.
-For you.
-Look, man.
-I told you that I'm not--
-It's a bad move.
-It doesn't solve your real problem.
-My real problem. What's that?
It's not Tuco.
It's keeping it secret.
A dead Tuco draws
Salamancas like flies.
Cartel noses into the business.
Looks for who hit one of theirs.
You gonna be able to
keep your secrets then?
Something's gotta give.
With you, without you, I don't care.
But something's gonna happen.
MIKE:
Hmm. Well, you said it yourself.
You don't need him dead.
You need him to go away.
You mean snitch?
Man, I drop a dime on Tuco,
who do you think the cartel looks at? Me.
I call the cops, I get picked up too.
I'm what you call a "known associate."
So I'm locked up with Tuco...
...who's looking for the guy
that put him there.
-Tell me how that helps me.
-You won't have to talk to the cops.
You won't have to do any time.
There's no killing,
but your Tuco problem...
...it goes away.
[LATIN MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
-It's all there.
-Shh.
Let the man count.
We're good.
So...
...until next time, huh?
Tuco.
Okay.
Go.
DOMINGO:
Okay.
I'll see you next week, Tuco.
-Nacho.
NACHO: Yeah, see you, Domingo.
He's got good numbers.
He's hustling.
What do you think?
Solid?
[SNIFFS]
Yes, I would like to
report a fight going on...
...at the El Michoacano restaurant on
the 5000 block of Isleta Boulevard.
There is a man
threatening another man with a gun.
It looks to be some sort of gang thing.
Oh, sorry.
I'm a passerby.
I don't wanna get involved.
What the fuck?
Did you see that?
-See what?
-That old man.
He just hit my car.
[BELL JINGLES]
TUCO:
Hey.
MIKE:
Hello. Oh.
Well, let me see. Um....
Give me the number four,
the pollo, por favor.
-That's to go.
-Yes, sir.
TUCO:
Hey, you.
Hey, gramps.
You just hit my car.
You talking to me?
[LAUGHS]
Check out Mr. Magoo here.
Yes, sir.
You see that car that you
parked your piece of shit next to?
That's mine.
You just ran into it.
No, I don't think I did.
You calling me a liar?
Oh. Uh....
No.
Hey.
I saw it too.
Gonna stand here and deny it?
Oh, guys. I don't know what to tell you.
I'm not aware of hitting anyone's car.
But if I did, I apologize.
So....
$6.33.
MIKE:
Um....
You keep the change.
-Thank you.
-Excuse me.
[BELL JINGLES]
TUCO:
Don't you walk away from me.
NACHO: Hey, pops.
You better listen to the man.
MIKE:
Come on, guys.
Let's just keep things friendly,
all right?
TUCO:
I ain't your friend.
Look. You see that? You.
-You did that.
-Oh, come on. That'll buff right out.
You're gonna make this all right.
You're not leaving until you do.
-Fine. You got a pen?
-A pen?
A pen. We'll exchange information.
Insurance. I have very good coverage.
They'll take care of this.
I'm not messing around
with insurance, ése.
Cash.
Listen, I'm willing to
accept responsibility.
But if you're not
going through insurance...
...then I have maybe
20, 30 bucks on me, that's all.
Okay, now you're lying to me.
I saw your wallet.
You got plenty in there.
Take it out.
Let's look together. Jog your memory.
You heard him. Take out the wallet.
I just cashed my Social Security check.
It's all I have till the end of the month.
And I am not giving it to you.
[LAUGHS]
TUCO:
You're not?
I offered to do this the right way.
If you can't accept that, I can't help you.
Oh, come on, guys.
I'm gonna make this
real simple for you.
Give me your wallet.
And maybe you walk away from this.
I'm not giving you a damn thing.
No, homes?
You give me your wallet.
-Let's just stay calm here.
-Ha-ha.
You see me sweating, bitch? Wallet.
Wallet.
There's, like, 400 here.
[POLICE SIRENS WAILING]
You got some crazy lip on you,
old man.
Your life worth 400 bucks?
Tuco, time to bounce.
Yeah, go, go.
You, one lucky old man.
What the hell? Let go.
Let go.
Let-- Let go.
Let go!
[SIRENS WAILING]
OFFICER 1: Let me see your hands!
OFFICER 2: Hands!
OFFICER 1:
Hands up! Now!
OFFICER 3:
On the ground.
That all you got?
OFFICER 3:
Get on the ground!
[LAUGHING]
[FIST THUMPS]
Wow.
Look at you.
Are you gonna have to testify?
The cops witnessed him
in the commission of a felony.
My wallet in his pocket.
Had the gun.
He gets a five to ten stretch.
Twenty-five.
You definitely earned it.
Still, you could have gotten
twice as much for one-tenth the hassle.
You would've
done the world a favor.
You wouldn't look like someone
took a pipe to your face.
Plus, when Tuco gets out...
...maybe he comes looking for you.
Get to the point.
I'm just saying, you went a long way
to not pull that trigger.
Why?
[♪♪♪]