[JAZZ PIANO MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
-Wonderful.
-Are the leeks too overpowering?
Not at all. That's as good
as the one we had in Florence.
-All right, don't humor me.
-I'm not.
How was rehearsal?
Did what's her name behave herself?
She takes the whole section for granted.
I'm debating whether to say something.
I think you should. Absolutely.
Don't keep it inside.
-Ready for the chiffonade?
-Yeah, thanks.
After all,
if she's compromising the work....
Hmm. Well, it's debatable. I mean,
the Schubert is coming along nicely.
-It's more about morale.
-Mm-hm.
Morale can affect quality.
God knows the hoops that Howard jumps
through to keep the troops humming.
REBECCA:
True.
-You deserve a medal for this.
-Please, it's no big deal.
CHUCK: Your soy ginger marinade.
-I found a citrus one that looked good...
...so I thought I would try that.
Well, anyway, you are a trouper.
I apologize in advance.
Let's just say he's something
of an acquired taste.
Oh, how bad can he be?
Just in case, let's have a high sign.
How about the old Carol Burnett thing?
-Oh, where she pulls her earlobe?
-Yeah, exactly.
You do this and I'll say I have
briefs to read, and we'll get rid of him.
All right, whatever you want.
You know why she did that?
Carol Burnett? It's a great story.
It was a signal to her grandmother,
who raised her--
[DOOR BELL RINGS]
Seriously?
-He's early. You're a doll.
-Hm.
[BEEPING]
-Holy shit. Look at this place.
-Hey, Jimmy. Thanks for coming.
-Bring it on in here.
-Heh, heh.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, a little taste of home for you.
I had to look all over town
to find a place that had it.
-Didn't have time to wrap it.
-Well, thanks.
You're good.
JIMMY:
Yeah.
I'm looking for a place.
I've been staying at the Ramada.
Thanks for the help, by the way.
I found a few that I like.
There's one place,
the Beachcomber, it has a pool.
And since the McGill clan
is whiter than a pack of albino rats....
Figure I better work on my tan.
Seriously considering that option.
I strongly suggest sunscreen.
We're up about 5000 feet here, you'll fry.
Excellent point. Sunscreen.
Check.
So...
...a violinist?
And according to Chuck,
a crazy talented one at that.
I mean, wow.
Well, Chuck is very gracious.
She's being modest.
Rebecca is widely respected
amongst her peers.
Yo-Yo Ma came to our wedding.
That's....
Right on, man.
[JIMMY CHUCKLES]
About the wedding...
...I've been meaning to apologize
about that.
-I am truly sorry. I wasn't--
-No worries.
Please.
[CHUCK CLEARS THROAT]
So tell us about your first week
at Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
It was great.
I mean, they got me
working in the mailroom, which--
You gotta start somewhere.
I learned how to use the Xerox machine,
which is surprisingly complicated.
I mean, press a button,
a piece of paper spits out. Not anymore.
The thing is practically a computer.
It's like a goddamn space shuttle.
It's got, like, double-sided printing,
automatic stapling, you know.
Mm. I met some nice folks,
guys and gals.
Well, gal, singular, actually.
I learned everyone's name
and I licked a ton of stamps.
My tongue is like hamburger meat.
I mean, seriously.
Ahh. Ah?
It got-- The thing is raw as hell.
Then I found out
there's a sponge for that. Oops.
Rookie mistake. Ha-ha.
Well, it sounds like you had
a very productive week.
Yeah. It was really great.
Hey, guys. Um....
I wanna thank you for having me over.
This is like the best meal
I've had in a decade.
I mean, the fish is perfection.
And the....
-Risotto.
-Thank you. That was very kind.
JIMMY: Well, you're a wonderful chef.
You know, aside from being
super talented with the....
Yeah. You got a good one, Chuck.
I mean, lucky, lucky man.
Well, cheers to that.
JIMMY AND CHUCK:
Ahem.
Pardon me.
[CHUCK CLEARS THROAT]
All right.
What's the difference between a vacuum
cleaner and a lawyer on a motorcycle?
The vacuum cleaner
has the dirt bag on the inside.
[JIMMY LAUGHS]
CHUCK:
Ha, ha. Lawyer jokes.
Been in the mailroom a week
and I've heard maybe a hundred.
-It all comes from a place of affection.
-Sure. Of course.
What do you get when you cross
The Godfather with a lawyer?
An offer you can't understand.
-Very clever.
-Never heard that one.
And believe me, I have nothing but
the utmost respect for your profession.
I mean, it's the pillar of-- Oh.
Why do they bury lawyers
under 20 feet of dirt?
Because deep down,
they're really good people.
[BOTH LAUGH]
JIMMY: Oh. What do you call a lawyer
with an IQ of 60?
Your Honor. What's the difference
between a tick and a lawyer?
-Oh, no.
-The tick falls off when you're dead.
Bam! Love that one. You like that?
Ha-ha. Just joking.
I want you to know
how seriously I take my job.
I-- The--
Grateful for the-- Oh.
How many lawyers does it take to
change a lightbulb? Classic setup here.
Three.
One to climb the ladder, one to shake it
and one to sue the ladder company.
[REBECCA & JIMMY LAUGHING]
-Comedy gold.
JIMMY: I'm here all night!
-More. Go, go.
JIMMY: Okay, okay, okay.
Dessert, anyone?
We have a homemade blueberry crumble
with vanilla ice cream.
Yeah. Blueberry crumble, sounds terrific.
I love a fruit-based blueberry--
-Wait, I think I know one.
JIMMY: Bring it on.
Yeah, yeah. What do lawyers
and sperm have in common?
-Oh, just--
-Um....
Three million-- No, wait.
One in three million have--
BOTH:
A chance of becoming a human being.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Love that one.
Well, that went well. Don't you think?
Sure.
Thanks again.
I don't know what you were
worried about. Jimmy's great.
Yeah. No, he's....
Yeah.
So, what's going on tomorrow?
I've got the Gurnstetter deposition
at ten.
Back-to-back partner meetings
after lunch.
It shouldn't be a late one.
Thought any more
about what's her name?
It's your reputation too, you know?
Well, we start the Tchaikovsky
on Monday.
So I'll see what kind of mood she's in
when we wrap.
Smart.
What do you call 25 attorneys
buried up to their chins in cement?
-Not enough cement.
-What?
Oh. Oh, oh.
[REBECCA CHUCKLES]
[♪♪♪]
[DIALING]
[LINE RINGING]
KIM [ON RECORDING]: Hello, you've
reached the voicemail of Kim Wexler.
Please leave me a message,
and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
It's me again.
I think I found something
that could help get you out of there.
I'm gonna make things right.
Call me, would you?
[SIGHS]
ERIN: Hi.
-Whoa.
Sorry, I didn't mean
to sneak up on you.
I just thought everyone was gone.
Nope. I'm here late most nights.
By the way, I noticed in your office...
...you threw away a soda can.
You going through my trash?
No. I was just dropping off papers
at lunchtime and happened to notice it...
...in your trashcan.
I fished it out, so it's fine.
Office cans are for recyclable paper.
There's a separate big can
for plastic, glass and aluminum.
We take our ecological footprint
seriously.
Okay, so the big can is where
I should throw my empty Scotch bottles?
Heh. No, I get it. Go green. Good.
-Was there anything else?
-Yeah, one quick thing.
The brief you gave Cliff. Plaintiff's
opposition to the defendant's motion.
I have a few notes.
I think they're pretty clear...
...but it's probably easier
if we go over them together.
-Jesus, those are Cliff's?
-No, they're my notes.
I'd love to go over them now,
if you have a minute.
It looks worse than it is.
We have a particular house style.
Okay, no offense, but you're
a second-year associate, right?
-Yep.
-And I came in as a fourth-year.
That's right.
So why is a second-year
giving notes to a fourth-year?
Well, like I said, I know the house style.
-Does Cliff have you babysitting me?
-No.
This is just one associate
helping another.
Like here, the Roman numeral headings,
we use all caps for those.
And you indented them,
which is perfectly fine...
...but Cliff likes them centered.
And before I forget, we put two spaces
after a period on all our documents.
I know it seems like a minor thing...
...but it looks
so much cleaner on the page.
You went a tad overboard
with the quotations.
It's okay to present a quote from a legal
opinion, but when you use too many...
...it gives the impression
you don't know...
...how to write an argument of your own.
Heh, I'm sure you do, so....
You have a tendency to overuse
the words "clearly" and "obviously."
-Again, a matter of personal opinion--
-I really appreciate this, Erin.
But I was just on my way out.
So if we could continue this
first thing tomorrow morning?
Well, I was thinking we should just get
her done now. No time like the present.
Sure.
Let's roll up our sleeves
and apply a little elbow grease.
-Great.
-So I'm gonna get my favorite pen.
-And I will see you momentarily.
-You got it.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
[KEYS JINGLING]
[HIP-HOP MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Tell your friends, holla at 'em
Later you'll see them ♪
♪ Later, 'cause I'm the man of your hour
How you want it? ♪
♪ Diamonds or a champagne shower? ♪
[BUZZING]
♪ Ballin' hard as ever
Tell me what you gotta say now ♪
♪ Ha-ha ♪
♪ That's right ♪
Uh.... Miss Wexler?
KIM:
You can call me Kim.
Kim, it's 20 to midnight.
Are you asking me if you can leave?
Guys, I'm not your supervisor.
Don't stick around on my account.
You coming, Kim?
Right behind you.
Just finishing up this last one.
♪ Said she wanna search
Gonna see what he's in for ♪
♪ Other words, baby girl
Tryin' to get disco ♪
♪ Always in the fly's fit
They should put wangs on it ♪
♪ Skrilla Jones on my job
Do my thing, homie ♪
♪ They say everything bigger
In the Lonestar ♪
♪ Texas ride dirty
No top, like a porn star ♪
♪ Balls-- ♪♪
[WATER FLOWING]
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
[KNOCKING]
Hey. Again, thanks.
KIM:
Hey, Gesualdo.
-Could you skip vacuuming tonight?
-Hey.
Five minutes. Give me five minutes.
Here's how we're gonna handle...
...this travesty of justice.
Wexler v. Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
You want me to sue my own firm?
The filing's all typed up. It's ready
to go. This is not my area of expertise.
All right? So, first order of business,
we get a great employment law attorney.
Show them we mean business.
[KIM GROANS]
Come on.
Hey, look at you. Okay?
You're here at midnight
in this glorified cellblock...
...busting your ass for what?
It has nothing to do with your
performance. You're being mistreated.
Chuck is punishing you to get to me.
This is extortion, pure and simple.
No, that's Howard,
who has an image to uphold.
He did the same thing after the Kettleman
fiasco and Chuck was nowhere in sight.
-I'm telling you, Chuck is behind this.
-No, you are behind this.
I told you this would happen,
and now I'm paying the price.
I should have known better.
So now I'm keeping my head down
and I'm getting through this.
And I'm most certainly not suing HHM.
-Kim--
-Even if I won, who would hire me?
That would be career suicide.
All right.
-Then I quit Davis & Main.
-What does that accomplish?
It's the only way
to get you out of Dutch.
Because this is about Chuck,
whether you wanna believe it or not.
I give him what he wants,
he lets up on you.
Wow, my knight in shining armor.
That is some sacrifice, quitting a job
you've been trying to tank since day one.
That's not true.
I dig myself out of this hole.
You do your job, Jimmy.
Prove you can go one week--
Hell, one day without breaking the rules
of the New Mexico Bar Association...
...or pissing off your boss.
And don't insult my intelligence by saying
you are doing any of this for me.
You don't save me.
I save me.
Just please go.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: Oh, yes, Mr. Simmons,
I'll transfer you.
Hey. Is Erin in yet?
[SIGHS]
Goddamn pixie ninja.
JIMMY:
I owe you a big apology.
I have a medical condition.
GERD.
Gastroesophageal reflux disease.
I know, it's a mouthful, right?
It affects the lower esophageal sphincter.
I took a risk yesterday at lunch
with some onion rings, and last night--
-Are we doing this or not?
-You bet.
KIM:
Hey, Jerry, it's Kim Wexler.
How's things with the alumni group?
Top 50? Ha-ha-ha. Go, UNM Law.
Hey, I'm wondering if you've heard...
...that Santa Fe Place
is looking for new outside counsel.
They should really be considering
Hamlin Hamlin McGill. We--
Huh. It must have just been a rumor.
Yeah, let's grab a drink soon.
You too. Okay, bye.
I remember you mentioned your brother
worked in Intel's Legal Department.
I'm an attorney
at Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
Would you know if Intel is happy...
...with their legal representation?
[CHUCKLES]
That's flattering,
but I'm seeing someone at the moment.
So you know what?
Just call the main number
and they'll find me.
Yeah, no,
we had drinks a few days ago...
...and she said you had a friend who--
Oh, so they already settled?
I heard you ended up at Harvard Law.
Yeah, yeah. She was my roommate.
Listen, I'm an attorney
at Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
We're actually known for teaming
with other firms on large contracts.
Schweikart? Sure.
Yeah, I know them well. It's a great firm.
We met at that ABA mixer last year.
Yep. Bourbon shots.
That was me. Well, congrats
on landing the Honeywell contract.
Huge amount of work. You too.
-How was your lunch?
-Good.
-What'd you have?
-A turkey wrap.
MIKE:
How's the place?
STACEY: It's great. It's safe, quiet.
They allow dogs.
We can't ask for more than that.
I can't get Kaylee out of the pool.
By the end of the day, she's a prune.
MIKE:
Ha-ha. I'm glad she's enjoying it.
STACEY: Hey, I better get her dinner
started soon.
Go to the restaurant.
No, it's too expensive.
I have groceries in the room.
Don't worry about that. Take her out.
Thanks, Mike.
She misses you.
-You think you might come by later?
-No, not yet.
I don't want her to see me
looking like this.
How bad was it?
Well, I can tell you
the next car I get's gonna have airbags.
Well, whenever you feel you're ready....
MIKE:
It's okay, it looks worse than it is.
You give Kaylee a kiss for me.
-I will.
-All right. Bye, darling.
Whoa. Hold up.
What the hell happened to you?
I get it.
The first rule of Fight Club, right?
Let me introduce you.
This is my babysitter, Erin.
Erin, this is my grandpa, Mike.
Nice to meet you.
[JIMMY HUMMING "THEME FROM ROCKY"]
JIMMY: Thanks, Tim.
TIM: Good seeing you, Jimmy.
Listen, this clerk and I go way back.
We're like this:
But she needs a little finessing,
so can I handle it?
Yeah, sure.
Surprise. I bet you never thought
you'd see me again.
Mm-hm.
I need a summary judgment hearing
with Buschelles for Bray v. O'Connell.
And I'm hoping for Thursday at ten
before he, uh....
-Don't have it.
-Thursday at noon, perhaps?
Nope.
Thursday at two?
Now, that's my final--
You're pretty.
Will you be my new mommy?
What are you doing?
-What?
-That's a bribe.
It's a gift. That's how it works here.
Grease the wheels of justice. Give me--
That's not how it works. You submit
the paperwork and you get a date, period.
What don't you understand
about finessing?
I apologize for my colleague, she's new.
Is there any possible way
we could still get Thursday?
I'll give you 2:30 Thursday...
...the 14th.
That's next month.
We'll take it.
So does this go
on my official Stasi report?
I'm not trying to get you in trouble.
I'm trying to keep you out of it.
I'm gonna hit the men's room.
The men's room.
MAN:
He posted. Posted bail.
[WATER FLUSHING]
Hey, how you doing, Bill?
How am I doing? How are you?
You know, hanging in.
Word on the street is
you're over at Davis & Main now.
Lucky son of a bitch.
You know, dancing with the devil.
-How are things at the district attorney--
-Davis & Main.
Man, that must be sweet.
They give you a car? Bet they did.
-Yeah, they gave me a car.
-What kind?
-It's a--
-No, don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
[LAUGHS]
I bet it's German. Is it German?
Yeah, it's German.
The cup holder's actually--
So you got a sick office?
I bet you have a sick office.
It's pretty sick.
-It's got a little fireplace--
-Fireplace?
I'd kill my mother for a fireplace.
Hell, I'd kill her for a window.
You-- You have an assistant, right?
Don't tell me. Is she hot?
She's hot, right?
She is a bright young man
named Omar.
Omar.
Hey, you got a little something
on your, uh....
-Unh. Yep.
-Yeah.
That's vomit. Again.
The worst part? It could have come
from two different defendants.
Scumbags. They're all scumbags.
God, where are you living?
They put you up?
It's a corporate apartment. It's just--
Don't tell me.
Ha-ha. Christ.
Damn it, I gotta run. I'm putting away
some brain-dead suckwad...
...who tried to rob a library.
Good seeing you, Bill.
Have a great day.
Yeah. Yeah.
[WHISPERS]
Lucky bastard.
[♪♪♪]
Hello. Hi, this is Kim Wexler.
I did leave a message, and I was just--
Yes, ma'am.
Sorry to bother you.
Hi, this is Kim Wexler.
I was looking for Carolyn Lipitz.
No, not his secretary. I'm an attorney.
Yes, I did. I got your number from Chris.
Sure, I will let them know.
Okay. Nope, got it. Totally understand.
This is Kim Wexler
from Hamlin Hamlin McGill....
Ahem. Actually-- Hi. Can I just--
Would you tell him
I'll call him right back?
Okay, just let me know
when is a good time.
Got it.
Okay. Thanks for your time.
Hi, Claudia. It's Kim Wexler.
I'll let him know.
This is Kim Wexler.
I was looking for Jillian Cogan.
I met you last year at an ABA mixer.
You know I have a fear of heights.
Kids will keep coming every summer.
All right, just give me a call. Great.
Kim Wexler. I did call yesterday.
Okay. I totally get it.
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
Kim Wexler.
Hey, how are you, Paige?
You did?
That's-- Heh. That's so nice to hear.
I thought we hit it off as well.
Really? I....
I-- I couldn't be more thrilled.
I mean, the firm and I.
Absolutely, I'll tell him right now.
I'm sure we can get something
on the books tomorrow.
Day after, at the latest.
Thank you, Paige. Me too.
Okay, bye.
Yes!
[CHUCKLES]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
WOMAN: All right.
-Just follow my lead.
I will.
[CLEARS THROAT]
-There she is.
KIM: Hi.
-Paige, so good to see you.
-You too.
Kim, this is Kevin Wachtell, our CEO.
-Kim Wexler. Great to meet you, Kevin.
-And you.
Paige, Kevin, this is Howard Hamlin,
our senior partner.
-Pleasure.
-Likewise.
We're thrilled to have you folks here.
Kevin, true story:
When I was seven years old, my first
bank account was at Mesa Verde...
-...if you believe it.
-I can.
Mine was too.
Back when my dad ran the place.
Wow. I can remember the cover
of my first passbook.
-It was a silhouette of a--
-Cowboy.
A cowboy on horseback, yes.
Standing next to a cactus.
I loved that cowboy.
Far as I was concerned,
I was saving for that horse.
What the heck else is money good for
when you're seven years old?
[BOTH LAUGH]
We have a little presentation for you
in our conference room...
...along with snacks, and a soy
mocha latte with your name on it.
Oh, this one. She's a keeper.
-Shall we?
KEVIN: Let's do it.
[BOTH SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
HOWARD:
That couldn't have gone better.
-Pleasure to meet you.
KEVIN: I'll see you soon.
KIM: Thanks for setting this up.
-Talk to you soon.
HOWARD:
Lovely to meet you, Paige.
Whew.
-Congratulations.
-Right back at you.
I'll circle back with Paige.
Get the ball rolling.
Start talking strategy, you know?
Maybe...
...put together a list of staff associates
we can put on this.
I'll put Francis on that.
You've got enough on your plate
in Doc Review.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
CHUCK:
Coming.
-Hey.
HOWARD: Catch you at a bad time?
Not at all. Come in.
I hear clinking.
Does that mean
we have something to celebrate?
We sure do.
What are we drinking to?
Got a juicy one for you.
Mesa Verde?
-On retainer.
-Oh, even better.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Congratulations.
One of your golf course conquests?
Kim Wexler brought them in.
Fourth-year associate
snags a quarter of a million in billings?
She's probably having
a couple of drinks herself.
She's out of the doghouse, I assume.
We'll see.
Huh.
Hmm.
Interstate expansion. It's a complex case.
That's two, maybe three regulatory
commissions we'll be dealing with.
Months of work for HHM. Maybe years.
[SIGHS]
-Good morning, Rudolpho.
-Good morning, Mr. McGill.
Oh, sorry.
-I didn't know anyone was here.
CHUCK: Yeah.
I'm just dropping off
some Sandpiper stuff.
You're in early.
More like late.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Well, regardless of the hour,
good to see you here.
Yeah, I'm trying something new.
Coming in and working until nine.
It's easier before the place opens...
...without all the lights
and the phones ringing.
How about some coffee?
No, thank you.
Would you mind making me some?
I apologize.
It's just, I can't do it myself...
...with the electricity.
Sure.
No sugar, just a splash of soy milk.
I think we have it.
Kim?
Um.... Make two cups.
Well, I guess it's true what they say:
The early bird gets the worm.
Which is good, if you like worms.
[BOTH CHUCKLE SOFTLY]
-May I ask you a question?
-Of course.
Do I have a future at this firm?
We have a lot in common, you and I.
My brother left you holding the bag.
If it makes you feel any better, you're
not the first to go out on a limb for him.
I made the same mistake,
over and over again.
And now Howard has,
and he blames you.
It's a damn mess.
Jimmy ever tell you
anything about our father?
Not much, no.
My dad-- Our dad, he was...
...well...
...the personification of good.
I'm not sure he could even
see sin in any form.
Like he was born without the gene.
He ran a little corner store in Cicero.
Cigarettes behind the counter,
penny candy.
Nothing special,
but it kept food on the table.
And the neighborhood loved Dad.
He knew everybody's name,
what was going on in their lives.
This little corner...
...he made it better.
I was named after him.
Before that, he worked for
a lot of people over the years...
...and his dream was to be his own boss.
He put everything he had
into that place.
I was away at college
when he put Jimmy to work there.
Jimmy grew up in that store,
watching our father.
But Dad was not
the world's greatest businessman...
...and eventually he ran
into money troubles.
I had a clerkship at the time, but I came
home to help him get his books in order...
...set the ship straight.
Now, I'm no accountant...
...but I discovered $14,000
was just gone.
Vanished over the years.
Turns out Jimmy had pilfered it
in dribs and drabs.
Just took it out of the till.
My dad wouldn't hear it.
Nope.
Not his Jimmy.
He ended up having to sell.
Six months later, he was dead.
At the funeral, no one cried harder
than Jimmy.
My brother is not a bad person.
He has a good heart.
It's just...
...he can't help himself.
And everyone's left picking up the pieces.
Is there any coffee left?
No, I got it.
I'll talk to Howard.
Pour a little oil on troubled waters.
You're being wasted
down in Doc Review.
Good job with Mesa Verde.
[OBJECT CREAKS]
[BELL DINGS]
[SIGHS]
MAN:
Mind if I join you?
Hi. What can I get you?
Coffee, black.
It's coming right up.
Mm.
He really did a number on you.
Sorry, I know you?
The young man who did that to you
is my nephew.
Hothead. Always has been.
He thinks he's a boxer.
He should have shown you respect.
I apologize to you
on behalf of my family.
Apology accepted.
And you know what?
He should go to jail.
Best thing for him.
Teach him respect for his elders.
But not for eight years.
Less. Much less.
You see what I'm getting at?
Not really.
The gun charge, that's eight years
he's going away. Maybe ten.
Aggravated assault, the gun,
plus he got your wallet.
That's right.
I would like for you to tell the police
that the gun was yours.
Would you?
You're both a little
hot under the collar...
...about whether you
bump his car or no...
...but there was a scuffle
and he got your gun.
My gun?
Your gun from your pocket.
He got it, and that's how
his prints got on it.
And then I'd be subject
to the gun charge.
You're an ex-cop.
They go easy on you.
So you're a psychic?
I even twist Tuco's ear,
make him apologize.
And he serves for battery.
Nothing else.
I'm looking for the best possible outcome
for everybody.
And for your trouble...
...you take home $5000.
Think about it.
[SLAMS CUP]
[♪♪♪]