[MAN SPEAKING SPANISH]
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Go ahead.
Turn to the left.
[UPBEAT LATIN MUSIC PLAYING]
Clear the cab.
[DOG BARKING]
Step around to the back.
Okay.
Here you go.
[♪♪♪]
JIMMY: You know, I was willing to take
you to a more high-end establishment.
This requires a proper celebration,
so don't think that this counts.
KIM:
This is perfect.
Besides...
...we're pinching pennies now.
When we have steady revenue, make
the drive up to Geronimo every night.
-Till then....
-Yes, that, let's make that happen.
Okay, here's what you gotta do.
Type up your resignation letter now.
I mean, tonight.
-Tonight?
-Yeah.
Well, I mean, finish your
hot dog first, but....
Now, you put that letter
into Howard's office tonight.
It's on his premises,
you've officially given notice.
Tomorrow morning while he's still out
on the back nine chasing his balls...
...call Mesa Verde and your other clients,
bring them along.
-You get to them before he does.
-No.
What? No.
You gotta act now.
Listen, you do this the "right way,"
you wait, you tell Howard to his face...
...he'll sink his dirty hooks
into Mesa Verde...
...before you get the words "I quit"
out of your mouth.
Okay, Jimmy, I appreciate the advice,
but the whole point of this is...
...for you to be your kind of lawyer
and me to be mine.
I need to find a way to do this
that's right for me.
[KIM CLEARS THROAT]
[COMPUTER KEYS CLACKING]
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, Kim, can we make this quick?
I'm kind of swamped right now.
Sure. Thanks for meeting with me.
I only need a few minutes.
Great. What's up?
Howard, could we do this
in your office?
Please.
-Again, thanks for taking the time--
-You can just go ahead...
...and rip off the Band-Aid. I have
a pretty good idea why you're here.
So you're going
with Schweikart & Cokely.
-I'm sorry?
-I heard through the grapevine.
I'm not going to another firm.
I'm starting my own.
I figured I'd try giving it a go
as a solo practitioner.
Well, I, uh....
Wow.
I realized it was something
I needed to do.
The week Jimmy exits Davis & Main
you decide to leave us?
That can't just be happenstance.
It's not.
We're gonna be sharing expenses,
one office but two separate practices.
Smart.
On several counts.
Howard...
...I want you to know...
...that I appreciate my time here.
I'm grateful for everything you...
...and the firm have done, especially
the financial help with my schooling.
I'm ready to write a check
for the remainder of the loan.
-I need Accounting to get me that figure.
-No need.
Our gift to you.
I don't know what to say. Um....
-Thank you.
-You earned it.
Tell you the truth, I'm kind of envious.
Really? Why?
Something about a fresh start.
Back in the day,
right out of law school...
...I thought hard
about hanging up my own shingle.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
I was ready to take on the world,
make a difference.
Dad talked me out of it.
Wanted me to join the ranks here,
throw another H in the firm's logo.
Things work out the way
they're supposed to, I guess.
Kim, I want you to know
that I always pushed you harder...
...because I knew
that I could expect more from you.
Good luck to you.
Thank you.
[EXHALES]
[INTERCOM BEEPS]
HOWARD [OVER INTERCOM]:
Get me Kevin Wachtell at Mesa Verde.
Cancel everything
I have lined up this morning.
Calling now.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
KIM:
Hi, Paige, it's Kim.
Yeah, hi. Just checking that we're
still on for lunch on Monday.
Great.
And Kevin too? Good.
Well, before we meet, there's some news
you need to know about.
[BOX THUMPS]
[DOGS BARKING]
[LIQUID POURING]
[CLICKS]
I am not the safe choice.
The safe choice for you
would be HHM.
I believe, however,
that I am the right choice.
Why?
That suit you're wearing,
did you buy it off the rack?
Please don't tell me it looks like I did.
If it did, I wouldn't have asked.
So why do you prefer
a tailor-made suit?
Because it fits you, and you alone.
Because each and every stitch
was fretted over with you in mind.
Either you fit the jacket...
...or the jacket fits you.
What if I want a whole warehouse
full of suits?
That's a hell of a lot of sewing.
How is one single tailor
gonna get that job done?
KIM: I know your bank's needs in regard
to this expansion inside and out.
Having Mesa Verde
as my sole client...
...will take up the entirety
of my attention, to be sure.
But if this were beyond my abilities
I wouldn't be throwing my hat in the ring.
I would not waste your time.
Or mine.
JIMMY:
Hey, Kim, we're in here.
Perfect timing. I was just
getting the tour. Kim, this is Steve.
-Steve's the agent for the place.
-Hi, Kim.
Nice to meet you. Hi, Kim.
Everything okay?
Huh, uh....
-Wow.
JIMMY: What do you think?
I, uh....
-I think it's, uh, a dentist's office.
-Two offices for two dentists.
Each the exact same size,
with a mirrored layout.
Here, the other one is the next door over,
right beside this one, right here.
But they share one lobby,
one reception area...
...so egalitarian as hell,
not to mention, efficient.
Huh.
Oh. Also...
[BANGS ON WALL]
...sound-proof walls. What with the
drilling and the pain and the whatnot.
And the location, I mean,
holy crap, I think this is the place.
[SIGHS]
Kim.
Yeah, it's great, sound-proofing.
Hey, Steve, do you mind if we just....
Oh, please. I'll step outside to make
some phone calls.
Y'all take all the time you need.
Bad lunch, huh?
Mesa Verde said no?
[JIMMY SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
Okay, I'm getting mixed signals here.
-Is this a good...?
-Jimmy, I got it.
-You got Mesa Verde?
-Yes. There's nothing in writing yet...
...but the lunch went....
It kicked ass.
It was a little touch-and-go there
for a moment...
...but Paige pitched in
and she really talked me up.
-And then once that door cracked open....
-High five. Fantastic.
I had an answer for every question,
every concern...
...and I did not badmouth HHM,
not at all.
But I was like, "enthusiasm," you know,
and "personal service."
-That's gotta count for something.
-Shit yeah, that counts.
Exactly. So--
I mean, like, why were they even
at HHM in the first place? Me. So....
Then when we walked out
of the restaurant...
...when Kevin wasn't looking,
Paige gives me a thumbs-up.
But not the regular thumbs-up,
the double thumbs-up. Two.
-Double-barrel.
-Boom, boom. Just like that.
-I knew it. I knew you could do it.
-It was just.... God, it was perfect.
[KIM LAUGHS]
What?
I just...
...I love seeing you like this.
So are we gonna keep these chairs?
Does that mean you like this office?
Let's do it.
Hell, yeah. Let's do it.
[HUMMING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Yeah. Ernesto, the door is open.
As always.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
Ernesto.
HOWARD: It's me, Chuck.
-Hey, Howard. Is Ernesto with you?
No, it's just me.
Well, I expected a round of documents
an hour ago.
-We've got a filing coming up.
-I know, Chuck.
It's very possible....
It's likely that we're losing Mesa Verde.
Losing them? We just got them.
-Why? Where are they going?
-They're going with Kim Wexler.
She left the firm.
Kim left?
Oh, Howard.
Well, where is she going?
Is it Rich Schweikart?
-Or did Reeves and Green get her?
-No, not another firm.
-She's going into private practice.
-What?
Well, that's completely....
How is she going out on her own?
Why is she going out on her own?
Well, the why is the why.
The how is that she's pooling
her resources...
...with Jimmy.
Kim and my brother...
...partners at law.
A Svengali. The man is Svengali.
At any rate, back to Mesa Verde.
I'm gonna try one last Hail Mary.
-Chuck?
-Hm?
-Mesa Verde.
-Yes, listening.
I got a meeting with Kevin Wachtell.
He's coming in this afternoon.
But compliance law
is not my strong suit.
So if you have any details,
any arguments...
...bullet-point them for me now. I've got
about an hour before I have to get back.
Chuck.
I really need your help here.
Are you okay?
I'm going to that meeting.
Chuck, I don't know
if that's a good idea.
I can do it. Force of will,
and I've been getting better.
I know you have,
but the message that we want to send....
I know the message, that we
appear professional and not crazy.
I'm going to the meeting,
and the lights stay on.
Everyone keeps their phones.
Everything stays,
for lack of a better word, normal.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I will make it through.
Hm.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Yeah.
-They're here.
-Okay.
Hello, everyone. Sorry I was delayed.
Not at all, we just sat down.
Kevin Wachtell, Paige Novick,
this is Charles McGill.
-Chuck, pleasure.
HOWARD: Kevin, Paige.
-Nice to meet you.
CHUCK: Thank you both for coming.
And don't worry, I'm not here
to extol the virtues of HHM.
I'm guessing you've already had
to suffer through Howard's hard sell...
...first time around, so you've done
your time as far as I'm concerned.
What hard sell? It was enthusiasm.
-I gave them cookies.
-Cookies were good, as I recall.
CHUCK:
No, I'm here to put your minds at ease.
Kim Wexler is indeed the right choice
to handle Mesa Verde.
She's the obvious choice.
She's young, she's brilliant,
she's going places.
Let's face it, Howard, she's the future.
Two old guys like us, we're the past.
Well, that's a sad thought.
Sad, but true.
Banking law needs to be exciting.
It needs the next generation
to come along...
...and give it a big old kick
in the seat of the pants.
Really wake it up.
Let me tell you how boring I am.
I read FEC and ISO reports
for entertainment.
He does. I can attest to that.
Well, I try to stay up on things.
The rules are changing all the time.
With everything that's happened
with Enron and Worldcom...
...the government is extra vigilant.
These days the penalties for even the
most honest of errors can be devastating.
You need a sharp,
young eye to catch that stuff.
I mean, when you've specialized in
this kind of work for decades on end...
-...you tend to get kind of....
-Stale.
Stale. You get stale.
You forget about things like....
Oh, I don't know,
the Community Reinvestment Act.
Any bank such
as Mesa Verde looking to open...
...a de novo branch
is definitely gonna need...
...to show a healthy portfolio
of CRA compliance.
Duh. Ha, ha. Obviously. You guys have
all that covered, I'm sure.
Riegle-Neal Interstate Banking
and Branching Efficiency Act.
There's another mouthful, huh?
Boring.
Still, if you were to run afoul of it,
it could hold you up in court for years.
And by the way, if that were to happen to
you folks as you go forward without us...
...which it will not, um...
...Howard has contacts at the Fed
who could help sort things out.
-One or two.
-Mm-hm.
And then there's the SEC's interpretation
of Section 302 of Sarbox.
Blah-blah-blah.
Well, navigating that correctly
could mean savings...
-...of several hundred thousand dollars.
-They know that, Howard.
I apologize.
When you reach your golden years,
you tend to get a little long-winded.
Ramble on and on about details.
My point being your bank
is in excellent hands.
Look.
I take your point. I do.
But I have to say I have
complete confidence in Ms. Wexler.
CHUCK:
You should.
She was part of our team.
She learned from us.
You won't find better than Kim Wexler.
But no matter how talented
one individual may be...
...the needs of Mesa Verde
are too big to handle alone.
I wouldn't handle
your coming expansion alone.
Which is why you should
consider once again...
...enlisting a team of professionals.
Glad we did this.
Anytime.
We are there for you day and night.
-Lovely to meet you, Paige.
-And you. Thank you.
KEVIN:
Talk soon, gentlemen.
Chuck, that--
[CHUCKLES]
That was amazing.
You were fantastic. Truly-- Oh.
Chuck?
Get me home.
Ernie.
Hang on.
JIMMY: Again, we want to thank you
for accommodating the major like this.
You kidding? It's an honor.
For a war hero, I think we can
bend the rules a wee bit.
Well, we really appreciate it.
Major Talbott's grandsons are only
in town for one more day.
So it's great they get to share
this experience with him.
You guys are in for a real treat.
You excited?
-Yeah. Excited.
-Uh-huh.
So these are your boys?
No, I'm-- No, I'm the family attorney.
I just help when I can. So I called you.
Well, I'm glad to be of service.
And here she is.
Gentlemen, meet Fifi, the world's last
air-worthy B-29 Superfortress.
She's based in Texas.
And she's here for a quick visit.
Just kind of a morale builder
for the airmen.
The crew's on lunch. Otherwise, I was
gonna see about showing you inside.
Isn't she a beauty, Fudge?
Just like the one you used to fly.
-"Fudge"?
JIMMY: Yup.
Major Theodore "Fudge" Talbott.
His mom used to mail him CARE
packages of fudge during the war.
He'd share them with his friends.
That's the story, right?
Yes.
Well, sir, this certainly
must bring back some memories for you.
[MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
Too many to count, he says.
I gotta say, Major Talbott...
...it's a privilege.
So thank you for your service.
[MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
He says, "You're welcome."
Oh. Oh, boy, I envy you guys.
The stories you must have heard,
you remember any good ones?
-Bombing stuff, mostly.
-Bombing stuff.
Like-- Like, the war.
CAPTAIN: Did he fly over the Hump
or take off from India?
[COUGHING]
JIMMY:
You doing okay?
You need some water?
Yes. Yes, sir. Oh.
Nuts. I forgot his water.
Oh, hey, I can run back to the office.
Get him a bottle.
You could? Fudge, the captain's
gonna run back to his office...
...get you some water, okay, sir?
All right. That's great.
There's no rush. He's gonna be fine.
I'll be back ASAP.
Up. Up.
I thought I told you
not to say anything.
Go stand by the front.
The nose. Whatever.
Where did you find this guy?
You couldn't get a real war hero?
Like they grow on trees.
This guy owes me.
-I defended him when he couldn't pay.
-Defended him for what?
You wanna be a lawyer
when you grow up? Just fix the--
Public masturbation. Total bullshit.
All right. Keep your voice down.
You do not possess
the power of speech.
Okay, let's go. Let's go. Chop, chop.
All right, hands on hips.
All right?
Looking strong, looking proud. All right?
See the bomber, okay?
The bomber's the main point, so see it.
I see the freaking bomber.
You couldn't plop the dude in front
of a flag? Why'd we come here?
Production value. Showmanship.
-You rolling?
-Yeah, rolling.
Okay. Start the dolly.
Action.
You're part of the greatest generation.
You fought the Nazis.
Fought Japanese.
-What?
-Fought Japanese. I fought the Japanese.
This machine was used
in the Pacific where the Japanese are.
Why don't you shut up
and learn to take some direction?
-Japanese.
JIMMY: All right. Fine.
You fought all the dirty Axis powers.
Your band of brothers came together,
and you saved the world. You're heroic.
Not that heroic.
Just throw it away a little more.
Okay, good. You've got red, white
and blue coursing through your veins.
Look up. Picture a bald eagle soaring.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Shit.
Okay, just keep rolling.
Tights, wides,
just get me some good angles.
Back to one. Back to one.
Fudge. Fudge, right here. Fudge.
What is it, Ernie?
ERNESTO: Jimmy, man.
I'm at your brother's and he's bad.
Bad? How bad?
He's bad. Shaken.
I've never seen him like this.
-He keeps telling me not to call a doctor.
-He's been going into the office.
Yeah, more and more.
He had a big meeting there today.
Here's what you're gonna do.
Wrap him in his space blanket.
-He's already under one.
-Wrap him in a second one.
Make him some tea.
Or just, better, heat some chicken broth.
-Just let it simmer. Don't make it boil.
-That's it? No doctor?
That's it. No doctor.
He's just gotta ride this out.
Chuck will be fine.
Oh, sh-- I gotta go.
Rhubarb. Rhubarb. Idiots,
that's the signal. Get him in the chair.
Where's the air hose?
Stick it in your nose.
Come on.
-Sir.
-Hey. This is not a problem.
Do you mind if the guys and I
took a picture with you?
-It would mean a lot to us.
JIMMY: Yeah.
Pictures! He loves pictures.
Give me the camera.
-Here's your water.
-Thank you so much.
Thank you.
All right. Let's scoot you in.
-Swing you around.
JIMMY: Okay.
Everybody line up.
Smile.
Cheese.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
[CAR APPROACHING]
JIMMY:
You ready to sign? Let's do this.
What?
KIM:
I lost Mesa Verde.
JIMMY:
What?
KIM:
I had him.
I thought I had him.
JIMMY:
So, what happened?
KIM:
They're sticking with HHM.
Paige said they went over there
this afternoon for some kind of...
...courtesy meeting, or so she thought.
-And Kevin got his head turned.
-By Howard?
No.
Chuck.
Jimmy, I have to ask.
You still up for doing this?
What, you mean getting the office?
All of it.
I think maybe we need to...
...slow down and really,
you know, think about this.
Wait, whoa, nothing's changed.
Nothing's changed? We're about to
sign a very expensive lease...
...after a very sizable chunk of income
just went flying out the window.
That's why we're a team.
Something like this happens,
you're there to help me.
I'm there to help you.
Hey.
There will be other Mesa Verdes.
So you still wanna do this?
[TOOL WHIRRING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
ERNESTO:
Jimmy.
I did everything you said,
but he's not getting any better.
You did good, Ernie. Thanks.
Why don't you go home
and get some sleep? I'll take over.
He told me he wanted me to stay.
It's okay. I'm here now.
And next time you see Howard,
tell him you need a raise. A big one.
Chuck? Buddy?
How you feeling?
[WHIMPERING SOFTLY]
[TIRES SCREECH AND ENGINE CUTS]
Hey, how's it going?
I need an X-ACTO knife,
a ruler, wood please.
Hammermill premium paper,
20 pound, one ream and a glue stick.
Oh, and point me to your best copier.
-Best copier?
-Yeah, best copier. Come on.
[♪♪♪]
♪ Been a strange old week ♪
♪ With the stuff you didn't do
And the people that you meet ♪
♪ And digging up words
Like pulling teeth ♪
♪ Got a place, a number
And a name that she goes under ♪
♪ I guess there's plenty
Worse places to be ♪
♪ So why don't you do it?
Yeah, why don't you do it? ♪
♪ Ain't no harm
In having just a bit more fun ♪
♪ Whether you like it or not ♪
♪ Make no place
For dragging down your face ♪
♪ Don't you know
It's the best one that you got ♪
♪ So why don't you do it?
Yeah, why don't you do it? ♪
♪ Why don't you do it?
Why don't you do it? ♪
♪ Break that bank ♪
♪ You never know
You might draw blanks ♪
♪ Then again
It might sort you out ♪
♪ So why don't you do it? ♪
♪ Do it
Do it ♪♪
[SIGHS]
[SNIFFS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
He emerges.
Good afternoon.
CHUCK: Is it afternoon?
Where's Ernesto?
He was supposed to stay with me.
Don't get mad at Ernie.
He spent the day watching you
do your impression of a baked potato.
I told him to go home.
Get some shut-eye.
You hungry?
You want something besides crackers?
No, I'm fine.
[GRUNTS]
I'll fix myself something
after my stomach settles.
Really doing a number on yourself...
...spending so much time
out of the house.
You just had to do it, huh?
Couldn't stand to let Kim
have Mesa Verde.
-You had to swipe it from her.
-I didn't swipe anything.
We retained our client.
You and Howard never even
heard about Mesa Verde...
...until Kim brought it to you
on a red velvet pillow.
[GRUNTS]
[SIGHS] I need a shower.
And I've got a ton of work to do.
So if you're looking for a fight, Jimmy,
I just don't have it in me.
Jimmy.
Thanks for staying with me.
I know we have our issues.
But if things were reversed...
...I hope you know that
I would do the same for you.
[DRILL WHIRRING]
You're doing a great job.
You done this before?
No. Not like this.
But we learned about
fractions in school.
You did? What fractions?
Half inch, quarter inch,
eighth inch, sixteenth inch.
Hm. Wow. You know, I gotta tell you.
You are much smarter than I was
when I was your age.
Maybe you needed better teachers.
That could be.
Can I do the drill now?
-You promised.
-Oh....
I did, didn't I? Huh?
Okay. Get up here.
You're gonna have to wear these if you're
gonna handle the heavy machinery.
Why don't you have to wear them?
Because Pop-Pop's a grown-up.
And grown-ups get to be stupid.
Now, put them on.
All right. Now.
I'm gonna hold this
because it's heavy.
But you pull the trigger
when I say so, okay?
Now get your hand on it.
All right, you got it?
Ready.
All right. Ready. Set.
Pull.
[WHIRRING]
-Good job.
-Can we do more?
-Mm-hm. You line them up for me.
-[DOOR OPENS]
STACEY:
Hello.
We're back here.
-Wow. What's all this?
KAYLEE: We're making a special hose.
Yeah, that's a special hose, all right.
I made marks
every three-quarter inch.
Then Pop-Pop put a piece of wood down
so he doesn't ruin his table.
Then we line up a drill.
-Put the hole in the X.
-Huh. Wow.
I needed a soaker for
the rhododendrons out back.
Well, Pop-Pop's gonna have to finish
this project on his own. We have to go.
But we're not done yet.
No, I'll finish up.
But you, young lady, were a big help.
Give me a hug.
Ooh. Love you, girl.
Love you.
Thanks, Mike.
-You still good for Friday?
MIKE: Absolutely.
I'll think of another project by then.
Fantastic.
-Bye.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
-I have a lunch date.
-Break it.
I cannot break this.
Will you take your hands off me?
-What are you playing, osteopath?
-Temper, temper.
Oh, listen, Walter.
You are no longer my husband
and no longer my boss.
And you're not going to be my boss.
WALTER:
It would have worked out...
...if you'd been satisfied
with being editor and reporter.
But not you.
You had to marry me, spoil everything.
HILDY: I wasn't satisfied?
I suppose I proposed to you.
WALTER:
Well, you practically did.
Making goo-goo eyes at me
for two years until I broke down.
I still claim I was tight
the night I proposed to you.
If you'd been a gentleman,
you'd have forgotten about it!
HILDY: Why, you--
WALTER: You're losing your eye.
You used to be able to pitch
better than that. Hello? Yeah? What?
Sweeney? What can I do for you?
[♪♪♪]