[CLANGING]
[MEXICAN POP MUSIC
PLAYING OVER CAR STEREO]
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE]
[HORN HONKING]
[HONKING STOPS]
[GRUNTS THEN PANTING]
[WHIRRING]
[MUFFLED GRUNTING AND PANTING]
[MUFFLED GRUNTING]
[MUFFLED GRUNTING CONTINUES]
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHING]
CHUCK:
Okay, all set.
Thank you for your patience.
Didn't you say that the hearing is,
more or less, a formality?
Well, the real work's
already been done, yes.
In that case, I'm fine covering it myself.
Kevin and Paige don't need both
of us there.
That may be strictly true, but we wanna
send the right message, don't we?
-I'm just worried about your comfort.
-I find victory laps very comforting.
Heh.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
[GRUNTS]
Well done, my friend.
COMMISSIONER:
Good morning.
This meeting of the New Mexico State
Banking Board is now in session.
We have Mesa Verde here
with us today...
...and they're represented
by Charles McGill.
Nice to have you back, Charles.
Thank you. Good to be back.
I'm here with my colleague,
Howard Hamlin.
And may I introduce
Mr. Kevin Wachtell...
...president and chairman
of Mesa Verde Holdings...
...and Ms. Paige Novick,
Mesa Verde's senior counsel.
Hello, and welcome. I believe
staff has found the application...
...to meet the basic requirements
for approval. That's right, isn't it?
With your permission,
Mr. Wachtell would like...
...to make a brief statement
in support of the application.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Mr. Commissioner, ladies and gentlemen
of the New Mexico Banking Board...
...I'm honored and grateful
to appear before you this morning.
We believe that our proposed expansion
is in the public interest...
...both for Arizona and our own state.
For 46 years, the men and women
of Mesa Verde Bank and Trust...
...have prided ourselves
on personal service...
...and attention to detail,
second to none.
Mesa Verde continues to operate at
a Tier 1 leverage ratio of 11.2 percent.
Uh, hold on. Excuse me, Mr. Wachtell,
just one moment.
Sir, sorry to interrupt.
We noticed a fairly significant
discrepancy. See the address....
-What's going on?
-Let's find out.
Mr. Commissioner,
is there something we can clarify?
Uh, yes. Can you give us the address
of the proposed Scottsdale branch again?
Certainly. It's 1216 Rosella Drive,
Scottsdale, Arizona, 85262.
1216. Okay, because the application
I'm looking at today...
...clearly gives the address as 1216.
1216. That's correct, sir.
But in the original submission,
we're seeing 1261 Rosella Drive.
-It is 1261.
-1261.
I think if you double-check,
you'll see that 1216 is correct.
There seem to be
two different addresses here.
Mr. Commissioner, I have a copy
of our notice of intent...
...which was published in newspapers
in Arizona and New Mexico.
-It clearly states the address as 1261--
-Mr. Commissioner, if--
"1261 Rosella Drive." Yes, I have a copy
of the notice of intent too.
But on the actual filing,
the address reads "1216."
So which is it?
Mr. Commissioner,
if I may confer with my clients.
COMMISSIONER: Certainly, please.
-It's absolutely 1261.
You're mistaken and, with all due respect,
you're muddying the waters here.
Muddying the water?
Look. Just look.
Well, this is clearly an error.
It's 1261.
I know where my own damn bank is.
-Let's all calm down. I'm sure we can--
KEVIN: I've got a building remodel...
...at 1261 Rosella.
I don't know where the hell 1216 is.
I don't quite unders....
-1261?
-1261.
-Is this gonna be a problem?
-No. I'm sure it won't be.
Um, Mr. Commissioner, I apologize.
Unaccountably, there appears
to be a discrepancy in our filing.
So the correct address is the one that
appeared in the notice of intent, 1261?
It would seem so.
We'd like to request an adjournment
of just a few minutes...
...so that we can amend the filing
to reflect the correct address.
Well, I can give you
an adjournment, uh...
...but I don't think
we can get you back in today.
If I may, when do you think
you might be able to schedule us?
I'm being told by staff, they've already
done the research for 1216 Rosella Drive.
Our folks are going to have to go back
to square one on the new address.
If we could obtain a provisional agreement
today to allow the branch to open--
COMMISSIONER:
No, no.
All due respect, it's up to you folks
to submit accurate paperwork.
Maybe next time double-check.
Now, the soonest
we could revisit this matter...
...well, it looks like
six weeks from Friday.
We--
We can't wait six weeks.
Mr. Commissioner, Mesa Verde
has put effort and resources...
...into preparing this branch
to open immediately.
However unusual,
a provisional approval...
...would be most appreciated,
most welcomed.
-Time being of the essence.
COMMISSIONER: Charles, I'm sorry.
I'll see you in six weeks.
That closes the matter for today.
MAN: Will staff please note that
Mesa Verde will return in six weeks...
...at which time
we will revisit this application.
That's on the schedule now.
And we'll have expedited
all the official research....
[BUZZING]
This is not possible.
This is not possible!
Oh....
"1261." No.
-No.
-Chuck.
I don't understand.
I don't understand. It was 1216. It was.
I checked! I double-checked!
Chuck, it happened.
Now we take our licks and we move on.
This doesn't just reflect on you.
An office full of associates...
...and paralegals let this get by.
I did too, for that matter.
It was 1216, I promise you.
Everyone makes mistakes.
This was no mistake.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[CHATTERING]
I'm buying a round for the house.
BARTENDER: Yeah?
-Yeah.
Hey. Hey, listen up, everybody.
This gentleman's buying a round
for the house.
MAN 1: Yeah! All right!
MAN 2: Yeah! Whoo!
JIMMY: Come on.
-All right, lift with your knees.
JIMMY: What does that even mean,
"lift with your knees"?
I don't know. It's something sweaty
people say. Here we go. One, two, three.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
-Got it?
-Almost, almost, almost.
-All right. Right there, go. Go.
[GROANS]
You okay?
Nothing a few years
of physical therapy won't fix.
-Okay.
-All right, push.
Slow, slow, slow.
Corner, corner, corner.
All right.
-Yeah.
-Get that one.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hi, Paige. How are you?
Yeah. I mean, no. No, it's fine.
Uh-huh.
What?
Well, yes. Ha, ha.
Of course.
Right. I understand.
Okay.
Yeah, that would be perfect.
I'll see you then.
Great. And listen, Paige, thank you.
Thank you.
Uh--
Jimmy.
What? What's up?
I....
I just got Mesa Verde back.
-Seriously?
-Seriously.
Holy shit. That's unbelievable.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
I....
-What happened to HHM?
-Uh, Paige didn't go into it.
She said the filing didn't go through.
We're gonna meet this afternoon.
Hey!
What did I tell you?
Sometimes the good guys win.
[KIM CHUCKLES]
It sounds like
there's some regulatory issues.
Kevin's still worried that one lawyer
won't be able to handle it.
-You can.
-I'm gonna have to get a paralegal.
Maybe two of them.
I will pay for it out of my end.
No, come on, split it down the middle.
I need a Westlaw terminal right away.
I don't even know
who to call to get that done.
-These are high-class problems.
-But it's a major piece of work.
-This is major.
-Kim, you've got this, all right?
So take a moment. Breathe, savor.
-You know what, you're right.
-Damn right I'm right.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
It's Ernie.
Hi, Ernie, what's up?
Yeah. No, Paige just called me.
Uh-huh.
Did Chuck say why...?
So when....
Sure. No time like the present.
Okay.
Thanks.
Mesa Verde files.
-Chuck's ready to turn them over to me.
-Wow.
Really? That was....
-That was quick.
-Yeah.
I'm gonna go change
and get over there.
-You want some help?
-That depends.
Are you gonna carry boxes
or are you gonna gloat?
Uh, some from column A,
some from column B.
Ground yourself.
-Sorry?
-Just touch the thing.
[KEYS JINGLING AND
DOORKNOB CLICKING]
Hell, this thing doesn't....
-Hey, Jimmy. Hey, Kim.
-Hey, Ernie.
-Something's wrong with the lock.
-Mr. McGill had me call a locksmith...
-...and change them.
JIMMY: Yeah? Why did he do that?
[DOOR CLOSES]
Hey, Chuck,
why'd you change the locks?
Ernesto, I think we're good.
I'm sure you're needed back at the office.
-Well, I'll get going, then.
CHUCK: Thanks.
Bye, Jimmy. Bye, Kim.
-Bye, Ernie.
-See you, Ernie.
So, Chuck,
what's the deal with the locks?
Kim, I was hoping to have
this conversation with you and you alone.
However, I guess it's time
to clear the air once and for all.
Clear the air about what?
He sabotaged me.
-What are you--?
-Please, don't bother.
You and I both know
exactly what I'm talking about.
I don't.
CHUCK: Yesterday morning was the
worst professional humiliation of my life.
A single transpositional error
cost my client time and money...
...and permanently damaged
my reputation.
Then I realized... it wasn't an error.
Not at all.
A week ago last night
I was right there on that couch...
...barely conscious.
And Jimmy showed up.
And he sent Ernesto away.
My brother was gonna take care of me.
And in the dead of night,
he went through my Mesa Verde files.
-We don't have to listen to this.
CHUCK: She does.
You do.
For your own good.
Now, in these files are 13 documents
containing the address...
...of Mesa Verde's proposed branch.
1261 Rosella Drive, Scottsdale, Arizona.
Jimmy pulled each and every one, and
he left me here sweating and delirious...
...while he went off to doctor them.
You need a photocopier for that.
Where'd you go?
Some all-night copy shop?
With a little careful cutting and pasting,
he created duplicates.
Virtually identical to my originals,
but with one key change.
1261 Rosella Drive
became 1216 Rosella Drive.
This is sounding like a lot of work.
No one ever accused you
of being lazy.
Every other sin in the book,
but not that one.
If you're wondering if Jimmy's up to a
little casual forgery, you should know...
...in high school he had
a thriving business...
...making fake IDs
so his buddies could buy beer.
-You're going back to high school, huh?
-Hey, you and Mozart, huh?
You both started young.
He came back here
and put his new versions in my files.
And then, the next day
my caring brother took his leave.
He knew that I would use
his modified documents...
...to write Mesa Verde's submission
to the state regulator.
And so I did. Over and over,
I typed 1216 instead of 1261.
I remember thinking, "1216 Rosella
Drive. That's just one year after 1215...
-...the year the Magna Carta was signed."
-Jesus, Chuck, you are unbelievable.
So you're saying if we look in here,
all the addresses will be wrong?
Well, of course you weren't gonna
leave evidence behind.
I'm guessing yesterday morning
you waited until I left...
...then used your key to let yourself in
and return the originals.
No crime is complete
without the cover-up.
Oh, come on.
I did all this, what, for some business?
He did it for you.
I'm sure you didn't know anything
about it.
I believe he went off on his own...
...and did this as some kind of
twisted romantic gesture.
I think you need to lie down
with a cold washcloth on your head.
And now that you know,
you have no choice.
This is about a client.
A client who has been defrauded.
As a sworn officer of the court,
as Mesa Verde's attorney of record...
...you have no recourse
but to go to Kevin Wachtell...
...and make a full disclosure.
This whole song-and-dance is all about
getting his client back. That's all.
Not in the least.
-If knowing the truth, they still decide--
-You can't stand the fact...
...that they chose her over you.
I can't stand the fact that my own brother
stabbed me in the back!
I can't stand the fact you've deceived
and ruined this fine young woman.
Ruined? What is this, the 1840s?
What are you talking about?
-She's not ruined.
-Jimmy.
If what you're saying is true...
...Jimmy could be charged
with forgery...
...fraud, falsifying evidence,
even breaking and entering.
Frankly, I am sick about this...
...but facts are facts.
And what is your evidence?
My evidence....
My evidence is knowing my brother
for his entire life.
Chuck, I think there's another
explanation. It's a simpler one.
You made a mistake.
-I did not.
-You're working by lantern light...
...squinting over 10-point type
for hour after hour.
Mistakenly changing 1261 to 1216
would be the most natural thing.
-It could certainly happen to me.
-I did not make a mistake!
-I believe you did.
-I understand that you have...
...great affection for Jimmy,
a great many people do.
-But please open your eyes here!
-You made a mistake...
...and instead of facing up to it...
...you accuse your brother
of plotting against you.
You come up
with this elaborate scheme--
-He's capable of this. You know he is.
-I know he's not perfect.
And I know he cuts corners.
But you're the one
who made him this way.
He idolizes you.
He accepts you, he takes care of you.
And all he ever wanted
was your love and support.
But all you've ever done is judge him.
You never believed in him.
You never wanted him to succeed.
And you know what?
I feel sorry for him.
And I feel sorry for you.
Jesus. What...?
-Aah!
-Kim, what?
[PANTING]
Just drive.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
TEACHER:
All right, line up by class!
Find your buddy.
Okay, kids, come on.
Let's go.
-Come on, come on. Plant yourself.
-All right. Here?
Yeah, right there. About yea high.
Aim it up at me. Heroic.
-Heroic? Good luck with that.
-Just frame me up, all right?
Make sure you get the neck.
It's a low-angle shot.
-Okay.
-You know what, let me see.
-It's just base.
-What, am I dying of consumption?
At your age, you don't wanna look red.
It looks like rosacea.
-What's with all the...?
-Making it look like you have a jawline.
I do have a jawline.
You know what, you stand in for me.
Okay, crouch down.
Okay, move to your left.
The other left. More, more. Okay. Boom.
That's what I'm talking about.
You got it.
-Gotta be an easier way to get this shot.
-Not for free.
You wanna be a filmmaker,
grow a pair.
Here we go, picture's up.
All right, let's do this. Last looks.
Rhubarb, rhubarb. Nine o'clock.
PRINCIPAL: Excuse me.
JIMMY: Hi, are you in charge here?
-Yes, I am, and this is school property.
-You're just the person I wanna speak to.
It would be helpful...
...if you can get those kids in that
building to keep it down for a bit.
Just give them a worksheet or something.
Just two or three minutes, for sound.
This is school property, and no one
is allowed here without permission.
Of course not.
-You didn't speak to Annette?
-Annette?
-In the superintendent's office.
-Do you know an Annette downtown?
I don't think so.
Well, I'm sorry about the mix-up.
We're shooting what's called
an establishing shot. Five minutes, tops.
You're not shooting anything
until I'm clear on what's going on here.
The documentary.
We're making a documentary. That's--
Oh. I was told there was a display
or a plaque of some kind.
-Would you know where that would be?
-Why would we have a plaque?
-Because of who went to school here.
-Who went to school here?
Rupert Holmes.
That's who the documentary is about.
-I'm sorry. Who?
-Rupert Holmes, you know.
Rupert Holmes, the singer-songwriter.
You know, um, "The Piña Colada Song."
I mean, sure you do. I--
[SIGHS]
♪ If you like piña coladas ♪
♪ And getting caught in the rain ♪
♪ If you're not into yoga ♪
♪ And you got half a brain ♪
♪ If you like making love at midnight
In the dunes by the cape ♪♪
-See? Look at her face. Rupert Holmes.
-He went to school here?
-Yeah, class of '64. Still talks about it.
-But the school was built in '71.
Mm. He was a student in the old building
that used to be here.
We're taking a little,
what do you call it, artistic liberties.
Isn't Rupert Holmes English?
Well, yeah, and that's some great trivia.
But he spent his formative years
right here in Albuquerque.
Why don't you call Annette down
in the superintendent's office?
We'll just stay here
till you get official word.
-If you don't mind waiting.
-Not at all. Don't wanna break any rules.
Shouldn't take very long, I'm sure.
No promises, but I'll see what I can do
about getting the kids to quiet down.
Ah, that would be super helpful.
Chop-chop. Magic time.
Come on, let's go. No last looks.
The flag, the flag.
-Okay, remember, heroic.
-Yeah, you're a hero.
Big, big hero.
Gravitas.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
CAMERAMAN:
Go.
Dolly, dolly, dolly. Nice.
Nice.
[BELL DINGS]
Hey, Mike.
-Hey, Fran, you still serving breakfast?
-For you, sure. The usual?
That'd be great.
-Thanks.
-Mm-hm.
Anything good in the paper?
Well, was there ever anything good
in the paper?
Heh. Not too often.
-Hey, Fran.
-Hm?
I gotta ask.
-Does it ever snow around here?
-Sure it does.
This gonna be your first winter
in Albuquerque?
Yeah, I'm out from Philadelphia.
Yeah, it depends on the year.
Stay around long enough, you'll have
some to shovel. Don't worry.
That suits me.
I live up in Cedar Crest. We get plenty.
You can shovel my drive
if you're looking for more.
-Say the word.
-Yeah, well....
Um, miss?
Check, please.
[BELL DINGS]
[INHALES DEEPLY]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
-Yeah.
NACHO: We gotta talk.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
I've got something I need to know.
And I need to know it fast.
-What's that?
-We got hit the other day.
A truck headed south got hijacked.
Someone stole a quarter million.
Now Hector is flipping out,
looking for who did it.
Thing is...
...I think it was you.
They left the driver hogtied,
not a mark on him.
Anyone in the game would've capped
him but this driver, he's still breathing.
I thought, "Who's the guy who'd
rip off a couple of hundred thousand...
...in drug money and leave a witness?
Who's the guy
who won't pull the trigger?"
You.
[SIGHS]
I'm not here to squeeze you. You wanna
rip off the cartel, that's your business.
But here's the thing, I'm picking up
that driver. Hector's orders.
We're gonna see what he knows. And if
he knows you, that's bad for both of us.
-That shouldn't concern you.
-But he was in on it, right?
-Driver had nothing to do with it.
-Then who?
Just me.
You telling me you did this
without someone on the inside?
Not possible.
How did you know about the truck?
How did you know about the tires?
All I can tell you is you guys aren't
half as smart as you think you are.
-So the driver doesn't know anything.
-Not a thing.
-He hear your voice?
-No.
Right now,
Hector is looking at the competition...
...but he hears the driver say
it was some old gringo....
He didn't hear me.
Saw a guy with a ski mask, that's it.
-And you're sure of that?
-Yeah.
You better be right.
Why wasn't it in the papers?
What?
The truck robbery.
The cops keeping it out of the papers?
The cops?
-The cops don't know shit about it.
-How's that?
Is that what this is about?
You wanted to put the cops
onto Hector? Why?
You are nothing to him.
He forgot all about you.
I haven't forgotten him.
You put me in the shit...
...just 'cause you got it in
for Hector Salamanca?
Listen, you put the cops on him,
you put them on me.
Doing it for the money, I get it.
But this shit, that's insane.
You need to calm yourself down.
And you need to take that hand
out of that pocket.
[SIGHS]
And just so you know, it's over.
I'm done with your boss.
Whatever.
MIKE:
Why wasn't it in the papers?
NACHO:
Because we cleaned it up.
-How's that?
-We got lucky.
After you left,
a Good Samaritan came along and said:
"Oh, my God. Oh, my God."
He cut the driver loose. The driver
called us, we came out, got the truck.
Made it like it never happened.
And that Good Samaritan?
Hector shot him in the face.
We buried the guy out in the desert.
Like I said...
...we cleaned it up.
[TRUCK DOOR SLAMS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[SIGHS]
[FAUCET RUNNING]
[SPITS]
[SPITS THEN SIGHS]
JIMMY: How was your day?
KIM: You know, met with Paige and Kevin.
Interviewed some paralegals.
And this. What about you?
Finished the commercial.
I don't wanna oversell it, but I think
it might be the greatest 60 seconds...
...in the history of television.
Tomorrow morning,
somewhere between 11:18 and 11:35...
...stop what you're doing
and tune in to Diagnosis Murder.
I'll make a point of it.
You wanna talk about this?
Not now, not ever.
I'm just gonna say...
...you are meant for Mesa Verde
and they are meant for you.
So all is right with the world.
Good night.
Your brother is one smart lawyer.
The smartest one I know.
I mean, no offense.
He'd make quite an adversary.
You better believe it.
The kind of adversary who'd find
even the smallest crack in your defense.
Going against him...
...you'd really wanna make sure
you've got all your "i"s dotted...
...and your "t"s crossed.
Nothing for him to find.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[BRAKES SQUEAK]
[CAR DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Hey, how you doing?
Be with you in a minute.
[COPIER WHIRRING]
Remember me?
Uh....
No.
I got a weird feeling you do, Lance.
Tonight is a funny night.
For some reason tonight...
...I feel like I've got all the answers.
I'm feeling kind of like, uh....
Like Carnac.
You remember when Johnny Carson
used to do Carnac?
He'd give the answers
before the questions.
You know,
Ed would give him the envelope, yeah?
And Johnny would hold it up to
his forehead, and he'd give the answer...
[IMITATING CARSON]
...like Leave it to Beaver.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Then Johnny
would tear open the envelope...
...and there's the question:
"What did the dead raccoon
say in his will?"
That ring a bell?
Before your time?
All right, well, let's cut to the chase.
Um, that guy who just walked out of here,
his name is Ernie.
I'm guessing he showed you my picture...
...and asked if I was in here
the other night.
Now he's going to bring his boss,
who's my brother...
...and he'll ask you the same question,
"Did you see that guy the other night?"
Well, the answer is no.
You feel me?
-You murder someone?
-No.
-Rob a bank?
-No way am I that cool.
Well, I-- Sometimes I go number two
and I don't flush, but....
No, this is just a thing
between brothers.
And we're both lawyers, so....
Right? I mean,
that's a long and boring story.
You don't wanna know.
Is this gonna get me jammed up
with the cops?
My brother might make it sound like that,
but no.
It's just family.
Then I feel you.
-Hey, tell me about the cameras.
-Oh, uh....
They go to a VCR in the back.
It tapes for 12 hours
and then records over itself.
So I'm on there now.
How hard would it be to erase?
Hmm. I don't know.
Could be tricky.
And expensive.
Like a hundred bucks expensive?
Like two hundred bucks expensive.
You will go far, my young friend.
Good evening.
-Uh, "Lance," is it?
-Yeah.
Lance, I'm Charles McGill.
My associate spoke with you earlier
and he showed you this photo.
Um....
On or about the morning of the 18th...
...this person was here in this shop,
is that correct?
-Uh, on or about the....
-The 18th, early morning, yeah.
No.
Well, I believe you told my associate
that he was here and he made copies.
Yeah, but sorry, no.
Yeah, that's my guy.
All right, the, uh....
The night of Tuesday the 17th...
...leading into early Wednesday,
the early hours of Wednesday the 18th.
Were you, in fact, here?
Can we establish that?
I mean, I work graveyard...
...so, yeah.
Stay strong, Lance.
Was this man here making copies?
Yeah. It's like I said, I don't think so.
Earlier you said that he was here. Now
you're saying that he wasn't. Which is it?
Yeah, well, when that guy showed me
the picture, I thought maybe.
But now that I'm seeing it again, uh....
Sorry, don't know what to tell you.
Guess I was wrong.
Son, listen carefully. I am an officer
of the court investigating a felony.
-So you're a cop?
-No. No, I'm not. I'm--
Mr. McGill,
maybe we better get you home.
Ernesto, do not speak to me
as if I were a child. I'm fine.
[BUZZING]
I am not a police officer.
I am an attorney.
And I have a moral and legal obligation
to get to the bottom of this matter.
-The bottom of what?
-Forgery, fraud, falsifying evidence.
-Breaking and entering.
-This guy, is he okay?
-There's nothing wrong with me.
-Maybe we could just take a break.
Ernie, shut up!
[BUZZING]
You think about
the choice you're making.
I already told you he wasn't here.
What do you want me to say?
I want you to speak the truth.
I know he was here.
I know what he did.
Tell me what you told Ernesto.
-Stop trying to change your story.
WOMAN: Excuse me.
Sorry. How do we get this
to do 11-by-14?
No, excuse me.
-We are having a conversation here!
-You gotta switch it to Tray 4.
It's easier if I show you. Look....
Dude, okay, I don't want
any problems here, so just....
Get him out of here
or I'm gonna call the cops, okay?
-Do not walk away. We are not finished.
-I am done talking to you, man.
[BUZZING]
JIMMY:
Call 911.
Call 911. Come on.
[♪♪♪]