NURSE:
Father Brady's in the chapel.
Just push the call button
if you want to see him.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
When was the last time you ate?
-What?
-Food.
-Have you had any lately?
-I'm fine.
Come on, Chuck.
Let's go stretch our legs...
...get some air, a couple of hoagies.
You wanna get a sandwich now?
It's just a thought.
[CHUCKLES]
You remember that time I--
I accidentally invited...
...Kathy and Cheryl
to Mom's surprise party?
It was kind of tricky
out on the dance floor.
It was a fun night.
I just remember the whole family
cleaning up after you.
And Mom leaving her own birthday party
to drive one of them home.
Seriously, Chuck, we gotta eat.
Mom will be okay for a few minutes. It's
been three days, it could be three more.
Okay. Let's go, buddy.
Jimmy, you wanna eat, go eat.
I'll bring you something. Um....
Roast beef, no tomato,
Italian on the side.
All right.
Okay. Be right back.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA]
[SOBBING]
[MOTHER COUGHS
THEN CLEARS THROAT]
Mom.
Mom?
-Jimmy?
-No, Mom. It's me, Chuck.
Jimmy?
No, Mom. It's--
[EKG FLATLINING]
[DOOR OPENS]
So this is it then?
NURSE:
I'm sorry.
She has that DNR.
Is your brother in the building?
-We can use the intercom.
-No.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
Charles.
Is there anyone you want us to call?
No.
JIMMY:
Hey.
Chuck. Hey, Chuck.
Chuck, where's Mom?
What happened?
-She's gone.
-What?
When?
How did--?
Did she wake up?
Did she say anything?
No.
[♪♪♪]
[JIMMY PANTING]
Call 911. Call 911!
Ernie, get out here!
LANCE:
What are you doing?
WOMAN: Hey.
-Come back tomorrow, it'll be half price.
LANCE:
I need an ambulance.
-A guy fainted.
ERNIE: I got towels.
-Good. Something for his head.
LANCE: There's blood.
-Give me a cushion for his head.
-Okay.
Yeah, hold on, hold on one sec.
JIMMY:
Chuck? Come on. Come on.
Yeah. Chuck. Hey, hey, hey.
-Hey, Chuck. You with us, buddy?
-The copy center.
-Chuck. Buddy, you okay?
LANCE: 615 Gold.
No, he doesn't...
-...look blue.
JIMMY: Hey.
-We're gonna get you to the hospital.
LANCE: Lance.
JIMMY: Everything will be all right.
LANCE: I work here.
[CHATTERING]
MAN 1:
Hang tight, Charles. Almost there.
Watch yourself.
Coming through.
MAN 2:
On three. One, two, three.
WOMAN:
Transferring.
[CHUCK GRUNTING]
MAN 2:
This is Charles McGill. Late 50s.
He had a syncopal episode
at a print shop.
Witnessed by an employee.
Estimated loss of consciousness
was one minute.
His vitals are stable.
He's got a laceration on his forehead
that appears to need suturing.
WOMAN: Charles, how you doing?
Can you talk to me?
MAN 3: Seizure activity?
MAN 2: Not in transfer and none reported.
-No urinary--
CHUCK: Unh. Unh.
WOMAN: Any family members?
MAN 1: A brother in the waiting room.
MAN 3:
How much fluid did you give him?
MAN 1: That's the first liter.
-Lights.
WOMAN: What's that, Charles?
-Turn off the lights.
WOMAN: Can't do that right now, sweetie.
-Oh, God.
WOMAN: You fell and hit your head.
We need to do tests.
-No, no.
WOMAN: We need the lights to help you.
MAN 3:
Charles, squeeze my hand?
-Really hard.
-It's-- The lights.
-What is that?
WOMAN: Just checking your oxygen...
-...Charles. Do you have any allergies?
-Ow. No.
WOMAN: Are you on any medication?
-Unh. No.
WOMAN: I'll move your arms and legs,
you tell me if there's any pain.
MAN 4: Did you get an EKG?
-The what?
MAN 3: Gentlemen, did we get an EKG?
-What?
MAN 2: He's on a five lead now,
we didn't get a 12 lead.
-No.
MAN 3: Trisha, we'll need a 12 lead.
No EKG, no EKG.
WOMAN:
Yes, Charles. We need to do an EKG.
No, you don't understand.
I have a condition.
MAN 3: Charles.
-I have a hypersensitivity to electricity.
MAN 3: Charles, please push your feet
against my hands.
WOMAN: --head and your neck,
make sure your heart's all right.
No, I have a condition.
MAN 3: Can I get a light?
-I did not give my consent.
-You have no right.
WOMAN: We need to monitor your heart.
Take these out of here.
WOMAN: Just relax.
MAN 3: Charles?
-Put the lights out please.
MAN 3: Please stay calm, Charles.
You need to cooperate with us.
This is gonna be very easy.
We're just gonna draw a bit of blood,
suture your wound...
...and do a simple CAT scan.
-No, no CAT scan!
MAN 3: Calm, calm.
-No CAT scan!
MAN 3: Can we get restraints?
-You don't understand.
MAN 3: Come in here.
-Turn off the lights.
MAN 3: Restrain him.
MAN 3: Charles.
-You're killing me.
MAN 3: Calm down, calm down, Charles.
This is gonna get everything
figured out for you.
We got you.
Just keep your head down.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA]
How's he doing?
I'd love to tell you, but we can't know
for sure until we do those tests.
-You know what I'm gonna say.
-Can't you go old-school?
Look at his pupils, use a stethoscope.
He doesn't want to be here.
What he wants and what he needs
are two very different things, Jimmy.
We don't know if he lost consciousness
because of a heart-related issue...
...or if it was a mild stroke.
We don't know if his spine has been
injured, if his brain has swelling.
He likely has a concussion at least.
Chuck is once again
refusing these tests...
...because they involve being
"bombarded by electricity."
His words.
Nothing has changed
since the last time he was in here.
-Look, I don't know how to explain this--
-I'm not committing him.
What about a temporary
emergency guardianship?
I mean, he fits the parameters.
You're telling me...
...he's in need of medical care so urgent
that we can't wait on court procedure.
Most certainly.
And Chuck is not able
to understand the consequences.
-I mean, he can understand them, but--
-Absolutely.
-A judge will see it that way too.
-Then I take him home and it's over.
Pending results
and proper treatment, yes.
I know a judge we can call right now.
Let me be the one to tell him.
[OBJECTS CLATTER]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Hey, buddy. How's it going?
Chuck.
Well, if it isn't Johnny On-the-Spot.
-What? What does that mean?
-Is Ernesto out there?
-Yeah. Can I get you something--
-Ernesto!
-Come in here, please!
-Just take it easy.
Ernesto!
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
JIMMY:
Just put your stuff in there.
I got him.
ERNIE:
How are you feeling?
Ernesto, how long was I unconscious
in that print shop?
ERNIE:
I'm not sure.
Thirty seconds? A minute?
Two minutes?
ERNIE:
I'd say a minute, you were in and out.
And how long was I lying on the floor
before the ambulance arrived?
About ten minutes, I think,
but I didn't look at the clock.
And yet you were there.
Chuck, can we, uh--?
There's only one way
you could've gotten there so quickly.
You never left.
I think you're getting all wound up.
Can you just take a few deep breaths?
CHUCK: You bribed him,
that kid behind the counter.
-What?
-Between the time Ernesto left...
...and I arrived, you paid that halfwit
to swear he never laid eyes on you.
And then you stuck around to watch.
-Why? Just wanted to see me suffer?
-Mr. McGill.
CHUCK:
Wanted to have a laugh at my expense?
I called him.
CHUCK:
What?
ERNIE:
I called Jimmy before I picked you up.
He showed up when he did
because I called him.
I was worried about you and I just....
I called him.
I'm sorry.
Get out.
Both of you.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Chuck, there's something that I have
to do, and I'm really sorry.
I'm really, truly sorry,
but I gotta do it, and it's for you.
You're trying to have me committed.
-No, it's a temporary--
-Temporary emergency guardianship.
Tomato, "tomahto."
You finally got me where you want me.
JIMMY: You look beat. Why don't you
go home and get some sleep?
I'm fine to hang out, you know.
Whatever you need.
No, we're good here.
Hey, Ernie. Uh....
How come you said that,
about calling me?
I don't know, man.
Look, I didn't wanna say anything...
...but your brother, the way he's been
talking about you lately...
...it's like he's really out
to get you, Jimmy, and....
I don't know, you're my friend.
Thanks.
I'll call you tomorrow.
I miss the mailroom.
[MUFFLED GRUNTING
AND YELLING]
[♪♪♪]
[MUFFLED YELLING]
[MUFFLED INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Are you familiar with
the Hippocratic Oath? You should be.
One of the oldest binding documents
in history.
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
First, do no harm.
This is not the way to treat my condition.
It's as though I had an allergy
to penicillin...
...and yet you persist
on treating my infection with it.
I appreciate the analogy, Charles,
but I don't think it quite fits.
We'll have you in and out of Radiology
before you know it, all right?
Then we can see about
getting that neck collar off...
...and get you moving around.
[WHEEZES]
WOMAN: Okay, Charles,
the scan is starting now.
The table that you're on
is going to move.
You're gonna hear a sound
that might seem loud to you...
...but it's nothing to worry about.
[MACHINE WHIRRING AND RATTLING]
WOMAN [WARPED]:
You're doing good, Charles, good job.
We're almost there.
MAN [ON TV]: Okay,
Heather is a 27-year-old fitness freak...
...who loved Preston...
...but openly admits
thinking of him as a walking wallet.
KIM:
Still no word?
JIMMY:
Jesus, how long is this gonna take?
She said the whole test
would be like ten minutes.
KIM:
Maybe they had to start over.
JIMMY:
What, 20 times?
He should be home.
Jimmy, you're doing the right thing.
[CHATTERING ON TV]
Would you get your work out, please...
...because God knows
how much longer we're gonna be here.
I'd feel better if you were doing
something, you know, unhospitally.
"Unhospitally." I'm on it.
MAN 1 [ON TV]:
Mr. Bergman? Mr. Bergman!
MAN 2: That was Preston's lawyer,
he thinks he knows who killed him.
WOMAN: Who?
MAN 3: Who?
You know what,
I'm gonna go ask for an update.
Okay, yeah. Good idea.
JIMMY [ON TV]:
You are the greatest generation.
-Jimmy.
-You didn't start World War II...
...but you sure as heck finished it.
And if that weren't enough, you sent
a rocket 300 feet tall to the moon.
Now, in your golden years,
you need someone looking out for you...
...someone you can trust...
...a man who says what he does
and does what he says.
-When you need someone to count on....
-Give me Jimmy.
Give me Jimmy.
Give me Jimmy, because moxie
is in such short supply these days.
JIMMY:
Jimmy McGill, a lawyer you can trust.
That's really good, Jimmy.
You made a really good commercial.
Thanks.
[CHATTERING ON TV]
Jimmy.
JIMMY:
Oh, finally.
So how is he?
Good news is that, physically,
he's okay.
The radiologist said everything
looks normal with his head and spine.
So we took his neck collar off.
His head wound will heal just fine.
We gave him a tetanus shot because his
immunization records were not current.
I'm sure that's no surprise to you.
-And his heart?
-Strong. The EKG was normal.
As far as losing consciousness...
...my best guess is Charles had
what's called a stress-related syncope.
It's basically a panic attack.
No signs of stroke or cardiac events.
However, there was...
...a complication.
JIMMY:
Chuck, hey, buddy, it's me.
They said everything looks good, so let's
get you out of here. What do you say?
What's wrong with him? Whatever you
gave him should've worn off, right?
We watched him for several hours.
We even gave him
what's called a reversal agent...
...so, yes, the sedative wore off.
This is something else.
What?
We think it's a state
of self-induced catatonia.
"We." Always with the "we."
I think it's you.
You're the only doctor in the room.
I think you fried his brain
with that machine.
-Jimmy.
-Sorry, this is bullshit.
Jimmy.
What next?
When I first treated Charles, he was
in a similar state, wouldn't you agree?
I have to believe that it's just a matter
of time before he comes out of it.
"Matter of time."
Fine, then, I'll wait right here.
[GUNSHOT]
LAWSON:
Shot left, 1.5 minutes.
How many rounds
have gone through the tube?
For a 7.62 you can put 3500 through it
and never know.
It's about how tight she shoots...
...and this one's tight as they come.
I'd say there's a breeze picking up
down range.
-Your barrel gonna be cold?
-Let's suppose so.
Well, then you'd better have
paid attention to that shot.
I better have.
Adjusting right, 1.5 minutes.
Send it.
Hit.
Center hit.
LAWSON: I suggest you don't change up
your ammo.
Stick with the 168 grain boat tail,
hollow point.
If it's an open shot, that is.
Now, if you gotta shoot through
a heavy window, I'll up you to 180.
But as you know,
you'll have to recalculate the shot.
One-sixty-eight will do it.
-How many boxes?
-Just the one.
No, it's on the house.
One last thing.
No offense.
None taken.
[SIGHS]
Jimmy.
-Can I get some water?
-Chuck.
Hey, buddy, you're back with us.
-Are you...?
-Can I get some water, please?
Yeah, yeah, water.
[CHUCK GRUNTING]
[CHUCK GASPS]
JIMMY:
Oh, shit. Sorry.
Want some more?
Last thing I remember
was that machine they put me in.
How long was I out for?
It was 20 hours.
And next order of business,
get you the hell out of here.
Where to next?
Some insane asylum in Las Cruces?
Some place you can really tuck me away
but good?
Home, Chuck. You're going home.
Your heart's okay,
and so's that crack on your head.
So that's all I wanted to know.
What about the TEG?
T stands for temporary, right?
[CHUCK GROANS]
You wanna go to bed?
No, no, it's-- It's cooler down here.
What can I get you?
I'll make you some tea.
Uh, the good stuff. Not that brown water
they have at the hospital.
I'm fine.
-I'll make you some tea.
-Jimmy.
No.
Just....
You've done your duty.
You can go now.
That came out a bit harsh.
Look, I've been zapped
and poked and prodded...
...and now I just....
I wanna be left alone.
If things go south for you again,
how am I even gonna know?
I'm fine. I promise.
See?
I'm feeling better already.
I mean, I don't even have a key so....
Can I get Ernie back here?
Would you let me do that for you
at least?
You need someone looking in on you.
You gotta eat, right?
All right.
Feel better, Chuck.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
[GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
[MAN SCREAMING IN SPANISH]
[CAR HORN BLARING
IN DISTANCE]
[BLARING CONTINUES]
[BLARING STOPS]
[♪♪♪]
JIMMY:
All right, I will get right on that.
I should have it for you
by early next week.
You have yourself a wonderful day,
Mr. Collins.
[JIMMY SIGHS]
Oh, there you go. Yeah.
Get the sunglasses out. It's very bright.
Gotta protect the old peepers.
You gotta....
Yup, looking sharp.
Bingo.
Uh, bye-bye now.
Okay. Folks, I'm sorry about the wait.
But the attention I give each client means
sometimes things get a little backed up.
Uh....
But I promise to get to each of you
in turn.
Mrs. Deshazo, my dear,
I believe you're next...
...but first, may I get anybody
some coffee?
KIM: Can I talk to you?
JIMMY: Excuse me one second.
We have got to get a receptionist.
Like yesterday.
Howard just called. Says he's been trying
to reach you all morning.
So tell him to stop bothering you,
and leave me a message.
It's about Chuck.
It's important. That's all he'll say.
Okay.
Unfortunately, my associate tells me
I'm needed...
...for some brief, but pressing
legal business.
I just need to make
one quick phone call.
In the meantime, who was it
who wanted coffee?
Yeah, okay.
This young lady will get you coffee...
...and also doughnuts,
if there are any left.
[WHISPERS]
Please.
I want coffee, but I do not want cream.
Hey, Julie, it's me,
returning Howard's call.
Yeah.
-Hey, what's up?
-Jimmy, I have just one question:
Are you behind this?
Am I behind what?
[TIRES SCREECH]
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
[KEYS JINGLING]
[KNOCKING]
Jimmy, I'm kind of in the middle
of something. Come back later.
No, no, no! Come on, open the door.
I know why you're here.
We can discuss it later.
Right now I'm busy. Goodbye.
[KNOCKING]
[SIGHS]
[LOCK CLICKS]
You happy now?
It's not right, me not having a key
to this place.
Chuck?
So, Chuck...
...what's up?
[TAPE RIPPING]
Um....
You got a little, uh...?
You got a little, uh, project going on?
Yeah, something you maybe wanna
tell me about?
What do you say, Chuck?
Uh, clue me in?
These walls are plaster and lath.
Completely invisible
to the radio spectrum.
No protection at all. I might as well
be standing in the middle of a pasture.
I don't know what I was thinking.
Should've done this from the start.
You should've done this?
With the, uh....
-I think these walls are pretty solid.
-What I need is a proper Faraday cage.
That's what I need.
I think we need to sit down.
Take a break, buddy? Please.
Do not patronize me, Jimmy.
I'm not crazy, all right?
I-- I never said you were crazy. That--
You're probably exhausted.
And justifiably. Hey, come on. Hey.
-Five minutes and then right back at it.
-I'm fine.
Come on, Chuck.
Just a break.
-Careful.
-All right.
[CHUCK SIGHING]
Oh....
Howard tells me you quit HHM.
I didn't quit.
I retired.
That's not what it sounded like.
Regardless, it's kind of out of the blue,
don't you think?
-He's worried about you.
-He should be relieved.
Relieved? Why would he be relieved?
You're his number one guy. Without you,
that whole place goes down the drain.
So you-- You retired, not just from HHM,
but the law?
That's not good, Chuck.
The-- The law needs you.
Just stop it.
And you need it.
What brought this on exactly, Chuck?
Huh?
Because I don't know what you are
if you're not a lawyer.
Hey, how are you gonna retire
before you get me disbarred?
Before you run me out of town on a rail.
Huh?
I'll be the only McGill carrying
the family name. You can't have that.
[JIMMY CHUCKLES]
Is this because you lost Mesa Verde?
So what? Who cares?
And hey, if you truly do think that I
ratfucked you on that thing--
Which I did not, but whatever.
Well, you know what? You get mad.
Take action. Don't just hide out in your
Faraday whatever. Your cage thing here.
No! No retirement for you.
When you're 99, you can drop dead...
...giving closing arguments
to Judge-bot 3000...
...which will run on electricity.
That's your future, okay? So--
I....
I can't do the job anymore.
What do you mean?
Of course you can do the job.
-I made a mistake.
-What mistake?
A simple, nothing little bank address.
1216 instead of 1261. I screwed it up.
I hurt the client. Hm.
I blew it, completely and utterly.
And then I blamed--
And then I blamed you.
[CHUCK SIGHS]
It's this goddamn electricity.
It's wearing me down.
It's wearing down my faculties.
My brain-- My mind--
It used to be-- You know, it used to work,
and now it doesn't anymore.
People got hurt because of me.
Time to end it.
JIMMY: What if I told you
you didn't make a mistake?
For chrissakes, Jimmy, stop humoring
me. Stop trying to talk everything right.
[JIMMY GRUNTS]
I ratfucked you.
It was me.
I would've made Nixon proud.
I changed 1261 to 1216.
It was me.
It all went down exactly like you said.
I mean, exactly.
I doctored the copies, I paid the kid
at the shop to lie for me.
It is insane how you got every detail
exactly right.
[SIGHS]
So you can relax, okay?
Because that brain of yours is chugging
along at a thousand percent efficiency.
Are you telling the truth...
...or are you just trying to...
-...make me feel better?
-I am saying it to make you feel better.
I sure as shit wouldn't be telling you
otherwise.
But, yes...
...it's the truth.
You'd go to such lengths
to humiliate me?
I did it for Kim!
She worked her butt off
to get Mesa Verde...
...while you and Howard sat around
sipping Scotch and chortling.
Hamlin Hamlin McGill.
More like Scrooge & Marley.
Kim deserves Mesa Verde, not you,
not HHM.
She earned it and she needs it.
I did it to help her.
But I honestly didn't think
it would hurt you so bad.
I thought you'd say, "Oh, crap, I made
a mistake," and go on with your life...
...like a normal person. But oh, no!
Wishful thinking!
[SCOFFS]
So can I tell Howard you're not quitting,
or retiring, or whatever?
Can we take all this shit down
off the walls?
I'm gonna go call Howard.
Jimmy.
You do realize you just confessed
to a felony?
I guess.
But you feel better, right?
Besides, it's your word against mine.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
[♪♪♪]