[KETTLE WHISTLING]
[CHUCK WHISTLING]
You can move the red five up.
Oh, yeah.
Thank you, sir.
Why do the cards have holes in them?
Oh, they're....
These are used cards from the casino.
Once the casino pulls
a deck of cards out of action...
...they drill a hole through them
and sell them to the public.
-Just a buck or two.
-Huh.
Look at that.
I suppose that's to prevent
people from cheating with them.
Yeah.
Makes for a good souvenir.
-These are from Caesars.
-Hm?
I've never been.
Getting dark.
I hate to say it, but I think
it might be time to kill the lights.
Oh, yes, sir. Of course.
CHUCK:
You sure I can't make you a cup of tea?
DAVID:
I'm fine, sir. Thank you.
CHUCK:
All right, then.
[♪♪♪]
[CAR DOOR CHIMING]
Just what I needed.
Drink up, guys.
Don't need you falling asleep.
Hey, you take care of that battery?
Oh, yeah. It finally shit the bed...
...but we swapped it out
a couple hours ago.
Okay, how'd it go?
No problem.
-Anyone see you?
-No. Dead over there.
All right.
Stay awake.
[♪♪♪]
[DEVICE BEEPS]
[CAR DOOR SLAMS IN DISTANCE]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Hello?
JIMMY:
Oh, hey. Come on in.
Hi. I'm Francesca Liddy.
-I'm here for the interview.
-Oh. Jimmy McGill.
Hey, are you running early,
or am I running late?
No, sorry. I'm a little early.
It's not a problem.
Never bad to be early...
...except in death and taxes...
...and some other things.
[LAUGHS]
-Hey, can I ask you a question?
-Sure.
Does that look straight to you?
Uh....
I think there-- That side--
I think you're a little crooked.
The bottom of the "M" there.
Yeah. A little crooked.
So you're coming off
of seven years at the MVD?
-I am, yeah.
-Here's a question.
How come New Mexico doesn't call it
the DMV like every other state?
Well, that's a great question.
Just like in Arizona...
...the Motor Vehicles Division
is part of the DOT, a division.
Whereas, in most other states, the DMV...
...or Department of Motor Vehicles
is its own entity.
So I don't know if that answers the question,
except to say that's the government for you.
You got that right. Well, I for one,
am not calling it the MVD.
DMV all the way.
What do you think you learned
the most working there?
Patience. Diplomacy.
You meet all sorts of people down there.
And most are really great, really friendly,
but you encounter some who are upset...
-...belligerent.
-What about old folks?
-You get your fair share of them?
-Oh, lots of elderly drivers.
After 75, they need to take their test again,
so if they don't pass...
...you have to explain why their license
isn't being renewed, which is hard.
What do you say then? Do you ever...
...yell at them? I mean, geezers, right?
How can you not?
No, I would never. No.
Nor should you. That was a trick question.
You passed with flying colors. Very good.
Heh, okay. Well, then...
...so Jimmy and I have very different needs.
His practice is mostly wills
for senior citizens...
...while I'm focused on
a single client at the moment, Mesa Verde...
...with banking regulations
that generate a ton of paperwork.
So I'm looking for someone
with an eye for organization...
-...and detail.
-Well, DMV's great for that.
Tons of detail in those driver's licenses.
We did see hundreds of people every day.
And you'd never want to let a mistake
slip through on their forms.
-You'd have a horrible cascade of problems.
-Sounds challenging.
So why the law?
I mean, why leave the DMV or MVD?
I have to imagine you'll be giving up
a good benefits package.
Good health care and retirement plans...
...but there's a bureaucracy
to government work...
...that ultimately became too frustrating.
I guess what you'd call it,
too much red tape.
I just wanna be somewhere
I can make a difference.
That's us.
We're all about making a difference.
And I see here both Word and Excel,
you're comfortable with?
-Absolutely.
-Excel and Word, wow!
Well, you had me at old people.
Hey, here's a question. Can you start today?
-I....
-Can--
-Yes?
-Fantastic.
Can you just give us a second, Francesca?
Absolutely. I.... Of course. Um....
-Thank you.
-Uh-huh.
What are you doing?
What? I like her.
"Can you start today?"
Don't you think we should see more résumés...
...like, a lot more?
She is our first interview.
-We haven't checked her references.
-So we'll check them.
Kim, you've been taking forever
searching for a paralegal.
-We need help.
-Haven't found the right fit.
Yeah, because you're searching
for perfection...
...and perfection is the enemy
of perfectly adequate.
-That's the bar? Adequate?
-She's more than adequate.
She worked at the DMV.
That's like the fifth circle of hell.
Look, she's overqualified.
If it doesn't work out...
...we can fire her. It's no big deal.
Don't you think someone with
actual legal experience would be better?
I've got a commercial airing in 11 minutes...
...so the phones are gonna be ringing.
I need help.
Can we give her a test run, please?
I got a good feeling about this.
Come on, Kim.
[SIGHS]
Now, getting these oldsters to call,
that's half the battle...
-...so they need to hear a friendly voice.
-Friendly? Absolutely.
Speak loudly and clearly...
...but be careful with the loud and clear
because it can come off as angry.
Be folksy.
-Put a little sunshine in your voice.
-Got it.
Okay. You need coffee or water?
You need to hit the head before things--
[PHONE RINGING]
Oh. There it goes. Heh.
Offices of Jimmy McGill. How may I help you?
I'm sorry. May I put you on hold?
Thank you.
Offices of Jimmy McGill. Please hold.
Sorry about that.
What can I do for you?
Uh.... That's right.
Jimmy McGill from the commercial.
Would you like to come in for a consultation?
Folksy. Be folksy.
Say, is that a dog I'm hearing?
It is? Aw. What's her name?
Yeah, Cracker Barrel.
It always helps to mention Cracker Barrel.
Well, I think it's great you let Margaret
play inside. It's a hot one out there.
I was thinking of going to Cracker Barrel
because they've got great air-conditioning.
Well, yes, I love their biscuits too.
Well, that's wonderful. Mm-hm.
Yes, I think a will is really important.
When would you like to
come in and meet Mr. McGill?
"Jimmy." Jimmy.
Always Jimmy.
This Friday is open.
Yes. Jimmy has a 9:00 free.
Will that work?
Fantastic. Can you spell your name for me?
And a number we can reach you at?
Okay, Dorothy.
Look forward to seeing you.
You betcha.
Bye, now.
I am so sorry. Thank you for holding.
How may I help you?
Well, I can set you up with an appointment.
Jimmy is busy at the moment,
but if you'd like--
You sound like you're outdoors.
Are you staying out of the sun?
It's a hot one today.
I'm sorry,
but Jimmy is unavailable at the moment.
If you'd like to leave a message, Mr...
...Ehrmantraut?
"Trout," like the fish?
Uh, I hear Cracker Barrel has excellent air--
This one don't wanna talk
about Cracker Barrel.
Yeah, patch that one through.
Mr. McGill will take your call.
[PHONE RINGING]
-Hey.
MIKE: Your new assistant's a real pip.
Yeah, thanks for crushing her spirit
on the first day.
Thank you, sir. You drive safe.
You the only one on this line?
Yeah, only me. What's up?
You free for breakfast tomorrow?
MIKE:
All right. This is what you're gonna do.
You're gonna go inside, buy a cup of coffee,
a meal, whatever, and sit in a booth.
Sometime in the next 10 to 15 minutes...
...a guy in an old green Chevy Blazer
is gonna pull into that parking lot.
He'll take a knapsack, and he'll go inside.
I need you to keep an eye on the knapsack.
Let me know what he does with it.
Does he take anything out of it?
Does he switch the bag with someone?
Does he leave something from the bag inside?
JIMMY:
Right, right, right. I got it.
MIKE:
Green Chevy Blazer, black top.
JIMMY:
Yeah, what's in the bag?
Is it money?
It's gotta be money.
Drugs? Is it drugs?
Something else? Well, um, I'm guessing money.
-Tell me I'm right.
MIKE: He is gonna be here any minute.
Now, I need you inside.
You gonna do the job or not?
JIMMY:
Fine. I'll do the job.
You charmed me into it.
[CHATTERING]
Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
May I take your order?
Uh, I'll have a Pollos Classic
and a coffee, black.
Would you like the bonus size
for 50 cents more?
No. Normal.
Dining in or to go?
Dining in.
-Will that be all today?
-Uh, yeah.
Your total's $3.19.
Thank you.
-Do you want any extra salsa?
-No. Ketchup.
One eighty-one.
MAN 1:
Hi. What can I do for you?
MAN 2:
Can I get a number four, please?
MAN 1:
Yes, sir.
-Here you go, sir.
-Oh.
-Have a great day.
-Yeah. You too.
MAN 2:
Yeah, I'll just take a diet.
WOMAN:
Hi. Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
MAN 1:
What can I do for you?
MAN 3: Can I get a number four, please?
MAN 1: Yes, sir.
-Is that for here or to go?
MAN 3: It's for here.
MAN 4:
Classic.
Sure, if there's one open.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
WOMAN: Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
May I take your order?
Hi. Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
-Will that be all today?
MAN 1: Is that for here or to go?
WOMAN:
Thank you. Have a great day.
MAN 5: Really?
-Yeah.
WOMAN: Hi. Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
Can I take your order?
Give me a number three. Potatoes, coffee.
WOMAN:
Would you like bonus size for 50 cents more?
MAN 6: No.
WOMAN: Dining in or to go?
In.
WOMAN: Will that be all? Four eighty-nine.
MAN 6: Yeah.
MAN 5: When you get behind the eight ball....
MAN 8: I know. You're right.
Yeah, no problem.
WOMAN: Do you need any extra salsa?
-Yeah. Give me that.
[CLEARS THROAT]
MAN 9:
Here's a number three.
WOMAN:
Here you go. Have a great day.
MAN 1:
Manuel, where's my 22?
MANUEL:
Coming up.
MAN 1:
Pick it up.
WOMAN: Thank you for coming to Los Pollos
Hermanos. Have a great day now.
Hi. Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
MAN 1: You ready or are you still looking?
MAN 10: Sorry. I'm still trying to decide.
MAN 1:
Okay, just let me know when.
MAN 11:
Can I help you?
JIMMY:
Uh....
My watch, uh, clasp is loose. It...
-...falls. I tried to reach it. Heh.
-Oh.
Well, I'm sorry.
Allow me.
You know, they say a nice watch band
is as important as the watch.
That's what I get for cheaping out.
We'll find it for you.
Where the heck is it?
Oh, don't worry. If it's in here, I'll-- Ah.
There it is.
May I clean this for you?
We have alcohol wipes.
No, it's been in worse places.
Thank you. That was very nice of you.
No problem. It's my pleasure.
-Is there anything else I can do for you?
-Uh.... No.
Thanks.
You take care.
MIKE: Tell me again.
JIMMY: Jesus.
-How many ways you want me to say it?
MIKE: Just tell me what you saw.
JIMMY:
He came in, like you said he would.
He ordered the number three
with potatoes and coffee...
...went bold with the extra salsa...
...and he paid cash
out of his left front pocket.
Took his tray of food, sat in a booth
on the east side of the restaurant...
-...and put the knapsack on the floor.
-Where on the floor?
Under his seat, between his legs.
Nobody touched it.
He didn't talk to anybody.
He didn't even look at anybody.
Finished his meal in five minutes tops,
and skedaddled. Didn't leave anything behind.
-And you're sure of that?
-I literally checked the trash can.
There was nothing in there but trash.
So...
...what's our next move, huh?
Are we gonna follow this guy?
Because you-- You got some
real James Bond stuff in here.
This car doesn't have an ejector seat,
does it?
I think we're done for today.
-That's it?
-That's it.
I mean, I cleared my morning.
What, we're not gonna do, like...?
Tail him to a new location?
Or, I mean,
we gotta sit on him, at least, I--
Thanks for your time.
Hey.
Who's got your back, huh?
Me. That's who.
I'll keep that in mind.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[♪♪♪]
♪ When the beef is on
I killed her ♪
♪ Heat so warm
In the pistol's pocket ♪
♪ If we got you in our sight.... ♪♪
Oh, Kim, the conference call
with the Arizona regulator...
...needs to be rescheduled.
Thursday okay?
-Oh, yeah. That's fine.
-Okay.
Francesca, have we got any more
of those dietetic butter cookies?
FRANCESCA: I can check.
-Thanks.
Welcome, folks.
[PHONE BUZZING]
Hey, Ernie. What's up?
Can't you just come inside?
Sorry.
Thanks.
What are we doing out here?
I didn't wanna call you because then
it would leave a phone record.
I was gonna come in, but then
I thought maybe Jimmy shouldn't see me.
-So--
-But you just called me.
Oh.
Guess I screwed up already.
Ernie, screwed what up?
Why don't you want to see Jimmy?
Well, it's just....
[SIGHS]
-I'm not sure how to start.
-You can start by just telling me.
Here's the thing.
I have some information,
but I don't wanna get in trouble.
Trouble with Jimmy?
No.
HHM.
I think I'm bound by confidentiality, maybe?
I'm a little hazy on the legal points...
...but if I tell you what I heard
and not Jimmy directly...
...like....
Like we have a buffer...
-...then legally, I'm safe?
-Ernie.
What the hell are you talking about?
I'm-- I'm just worried about Jimmy.
But if I tell him...
...I don't wanna get in trouble too.
Tell Jimmy what?
Lily, I wanna thank you
for bringing your mom down.
It was a delight to meet you, young lady.
Thank you, Jimmy.
Tell your friends,
even if they already have a will...
...it's important to get it updated,
just like you did.
-I'll tell them.
-Now, you remember Francesca.
She'll take care of you the rest of the way.
All right, who's next?
Mr. Witchell. Mr. Witchell, come on down.
You're the next contestant
on The Price is Right.
Jimmy, can I have a moment?
-Excuse me, sir.
FRANCESCA: Looks like everything is....
Apologies, Mr. Witchell.
Just be a second, folks.
FRANCESCA: Oh, my gosh. Have you guys had
the soup over at Cracker Barrel today?
What?
Hey, come on. I got people out there.
-Hello. I can't--
-Give me a dollar.
-Give you a dollar?
-Hand me a dollar.
-Come on.
-Okay.
-All I got's a twenty.
-Fine. Whatever.
All right.
I'm your lawyer now.
If anyone asks me what I know,
we have confidentiality.
-Why do we need confidentiality?
-Jimmy...
...what did you say to Chuck?
Oh.
Here it comes.
Howard, right? Did Howard call?
Relax. No. Let me explain, please.
Please.
Kim, let me set the stage for you, okay?
When I went to Chuck's place last week...
...it was like the inside
of a Jiffy Pop wrapper, all right?
There was Mylar on the walls.
There was Mylar on the ceiling. The ceiling.
He thought his brain wasn't working
because of the Mesa Verde event and so...
...I kind of told him that he was right...
...about everything.
I had to. He-- He--
Kim, he was broken. He was a broken man.
I couldn't leave him in crazy town like that,
so I told him just to make him feel better.
Doesn't matter what he says.
Doesn't matter who he tells.
-Because it's my word against his.
-Jimmy, there's a tape.
What?
There is a tape recording
of you talking to Chuck.
What do you mean? Who?
Who-- He-- He taped me? How?
I don't know how.
He just did, okay?
-Ernie told me.
-Ernie told you?
He said Chuck has a tape recorder wrapped
in a space blanket in his desk drawer.
Ernie was putting new batteries in it...
...and the tape rolled for a few seconds
and he heard you.
Your voice saying something
about switching 1261 to 1216.
So clearly, it was this confession of yours.
He taped me?
Yes, Jimmy.
But I'm not sure what he can do with it...
...legally, anyway.
I'm gonna have to do some research.
He made that tape for a reason...
...and we just have to figure out why.
[SIGHS]
Jimmy?
I gotta get back to it.
The lobby's full of clients.
Okay.
We'll figure this out.
Yeah. I know.
Sorry for the delay, everyone.
Mr. Witchell, thank you for your patience.
I see you brought paperwork.
JIMMY:
I gotta say...
...I would never have
thought to collect bottle caps.
Oh, it's a wonderful hobby.
What excites me is the hunt. Heh.
I can imagine.
Pleasure doing business with you, Mr. Tiller.
Why, thank you, Jimmy.
-All right, then. You drive safe.
-Oh, I do.
[SIGHS]
JIMMY: Is that the last one,
or we got any stragglers coming through?
FRANCESCA:
Last one.
Well, hey, thanks, Francesca.
You were great today.
You too.
Those folks love you.
Who doesn't?
And that's U.S. v. McKeever?
Right. No, it makes sense.
You were a tremendous help, professor.
Thanks for finding the time.
You too.
Thanks again.
KIM:
Francesca, could you do me a favor?
Can you go through the Mesa Verde files...
...and pull all the ones labeled
"CRA evaluations"...
...and sort them by date?
I need to have the most recent.
-Absolutely.
-Thank you.
-I'll join you in a minute.
-Okay.
So...
...just got off the phone
with my old Crim-Pro professor.
Oh, yeah? What'd he say?
Well, as we know...
...New Mexico is one-party consent,
so Chuck had a right to make the recording.
But you went to him worried
for his mental health.
You said the things you did
to make him feel better...
...which mitigates the admission of guilt,
at the very least.
We can poke holes in the custody...
...throw doubt the voice
on the tape is even yours.
Even failing that, its probative value
doesn't outweigh how prejudicial it is.
I think we can get the whole thing
bounced under 403.
Probably get it excluded outright.
So then...
...outside the courts, what can he do?
Play the tape for Kevin at Mesa Verde?
He hasn't up to now.
I'd have heard something, for sure.
Know what? Don't think he will. Howard
won't let him near Mesa Verde with that tape.
Howard knows it would make HHM look terrible.
If Chuck has a plan for this tape,
I don't know what it is.
At this point, all we can do is wait
for his move, then act accordingly.
All right, then.
Thanks.
Sure.
Oh, hey, what do you think? Um....
It's Etude in Blue over Daydream Harvest.
I wanted it to look like morning
over the Sandias.
-I like it. It looks nice.
-It doesn't look like a stock-market crash?
No. It doesn't look like
a stock-market crash.
It's nice.
Thanks.
You okay?
Kim, I'm good.
[♪♪♪]
[DOOR OPENS]
[PHONE RINGING]
Yeah.
Oof!
[CHIMING]
[DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Howard, what are you doing here?
-Chuck, do you have a second?
Did you-- You parked over on the next block?
-Oh, yeah. Way over.
-Yeah.
Uh, phone. Keys.
Hey, you have to hide them.
Everything okay, sir?
Yes, thank you, David.
-Give us a moment.
-Yes, sir.
-What's up?
-Chuck...
...this has been going on
for eight days now...
...and really, no indication
that it's going to work.
It will work.
I think I've been very patient...
...but the cost of these
around-the-clock private investigators...
-...is really starting to add up.
-Howard.
This is our duty.
As officers of the court...
-...we have an ethical obligation to--
HOWARD: Yes.
My brother broke the law.
-We can't just sit back and do nothing.
-I'm not talking about doing nothing.
I just want to...
...free up our minds...
...and be open
to alternate strategies, please.
Meet me halfway here.
[SIGHS]
I suppose--
I suppose we could limit
the investigators to just nighttime hours.
-Nighttime.
-Yes.
Jimmy will most likely break in
while he thinks I'm sleeping.
I mean, I wouldn't put anything past him.
It just makes the most sense...
...he'll try to steal the tape
under darkness.
You really think he's going to do that?
I do, indeed.
How can you be so sure?
Howard...
...I know my brother.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
JIMMY:
Chuck!
Chuck.
Open the damn door, Chuck!
Open the door, damn it. Open it. Chuck.
-Jimmy, go away.
JIMMY: Open the door! Open it now!
-I'm not opening the door. I am not op--
-I swear to God, Chuck.
Jimmy. Jimmy.
You taped me?
-You asshole.
-Jimmy.
You pulled that heartstrings con job on me?
You piece of shit!
[IMITATING CHUCK] "Oh, my brain used to work.
I'm sick. I don't know what to do."
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Asshole!
No wonder Rebecca left you.
What took her so long?
There it is!
Here we go. Here we go.
Here we go.
[GRUNTING]
Is this it?
Is this it? Is this it? Huh?
For this, you destroyed our family?
You happy now? For what?
For nothing!
Is that all there is, Chuck?
It's all the-- All there is?
Or did you make copies? Huh, Chuck?
You tell me, or I'll burn this
whole goddamn house to the ground.
Jimmy. Jimmy.
That's enough.
You need to step away.
Howard...
-...you were a witness to what happened here?
-I was.
And you?
I'm a witness.
[♪♪♪]