[♪♪♪]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Yeah?
MAN:
May I assume that you're armed?
Yes.
I do not wish to see your gun.
And if I don't...
...I promise you won't see mine.
Are we in agreement?
We are.
Expect two cars momentarily.
[CARS APPROACHING]
You care to elaborate?
It's not in my interest
for Hector Salamanca to die.
At this time.
Who is he to you?
-An associate of an associate.
-Hmm.
How very specific.
Who is he to you?
We had a disagreement.
He threatened my family.
I'm not gonna let that go.
But...
...you had let it go.
You'd taken his money.
Your family was no longer in danger.
And yet, still, you robbed his truck.
Shouldn't that have settled the matter?
Most men would've walked away.
But instead...
...you made an attempt on his life.
Why?
I understand...
...that a civilian found the driver
after you robbed the truck.
Hector murdered this civilian.
Correct?
He wasn't in the game.
I can't allow you to kill Hector.
However, I am not completely
unsympathetic to your...
...sense of justice.
You hurt Hector
when you robbed that truck.
You hurt his business.
His pride.
Quite effectively.
And if you were to hurt him
in the same manner again...
...I would not stand in your way.
You want me to rob another truck.
If you feel so inclined.
I'm done with that.
Then our business here is finished.
That's it?
That's it.
No more tracker,
no more of your minions following me...
...just like that.
Just like that.
Of course...
...I trust that you are done
with Hector Salamanca.
Goodbye, Mr. Ehrmantraut.
Wait.
You want his trucks hit because
you wanna disrupt his supply line.
Hector's your competition.
Why do you ask?
Because I'm not done
with Hector Salamanca.
[PHONE RINGING]
Offices of Jimmy McGill.
How may I help you today?
JIMMY: Hey, it's me.
-Oh, hey, Jimmy.
Listen, um...
...something's come up...
...and I need you to reschedule
all of my appointments for tomorrow.
Oh, okay. When do you want me
to reschedule for?
Let's talk about it tomorrow.
Sure thing.
Oh, and do me a favor.
Tell Kim I won't be back in tonight.
Will do.
Okay, that's it.
Have a great night.
Mm.
CHUCK:
You know you can wait inside.
You won't wanna hear it,
but this is for the best.
Please, Jimmy.
Whatever you think of me,
whatever names you're calling me...
...in your head right now...
...please understand
I'm trying to help you.
Here's what's going to happen.
The police will arrest you and I'm sorry,
but I will be pressing charges.
I told you
there would be consequences.
But I have to believe that
you'll face those consequences...
...and you'll come out the other side
a better man.
I know it's hard to see right now.
But, Jimmy, this is an opportunity.
That's why I'm doing this.
Not to punish you.
To show you...
...truly show you,
that you have to make a change.
Before it's too late.
Before you destroy yourself.
Or someone else.
And I believe you can change.
You'll find your path.
And when you're ready...
...I will be there
to help you walk that path.
Here's what's gonna happen.
One day, you're gonna get sick...
...again.
One of your employees is gonna
find you curled up in that space blanket.
Take you to the hospital.
Hook you up to those machines
that beep and whir...
...and hurt.
And this time, it'll be too much.
And you will...
...die there.
Alone.
There's my ride.
♪ Hurry down ♪
♪ Hurry down, sun ♪
♪ Hurry ♪
OFFICER: Sir, I need all
your personal property. Belt, ties, phone.
Rings, wallet.
♪ I said, sun ♪
♪ Won't you hurry on
On down ♪
♪ Struggling ♪
OFFICER: Need your socks and shoes
placed in that bag.
♪ If someday my kids are laughing ♪
OFFICER:
Put these on your feet.
Follow me this way.
Turn to the right.
Turn to the left.
Face me.
Left hand.
♪ It's on its way ♪
♪ Hurry, sundown ♪
♪ Hurry down, sundown ♪
♪ Hurry down, sundown ♪♪
[DOOR BUZZES]
-Right hand.
-Holy hell.
I thought they were bullshitting me.
How the mighty have fallen.
What the hell happened, man?
Nothing, just family trouble.
You're married?
No, disagreement with my brother.
That hard-ass, I don't blame you.
-So who you got representing you?
-I'll be representing myself.
-Sign here.
-You moron.
Of course, I knew that when you
left that sweet Davis and Main gig.
This way.
Hey, speaking of...
-...still trying to replace you over there?
-Arms out.
How's Omar?
Why? You looking to make a change?
And leave all this glamour behind?
-Hey, who do you think's gonna catch this?
-Depends on who's available.
OFFICER: Face me.
-You think you might be?
-Run your hands through your hair.
-Come on.
Don't you wanna
throw the book at me for old times' sake?
I'll see if I can work some magic.
But those decisions
are above my pay grade.
-Yeah? When did they start paying you?
OFFICER: This way.
OAKLEY: Heh, heh.
OFFICER: Sit here.
-I gotta run anyway.
-Left hand.
Just had to see it for myself.
Jimmy McGill getting fingerprinted
with the hoi polloi.
Well, I'm glad you enjoyed the show.
I'll check and see if I can get
your first appearance moved up.
Thank you.
It's pretty late.
Chances are you're spending the night.
You gonna be okay?
Beats the back of a nail salon.
I do not doubt that, my friend. Heh, heh.
Oh. Pick the biggest guy,
punch him as hard as you can.
Okay? Show dominance.
Right, got it. Dominance.
You do know how to throw a punch,
right?
Yeah, all right. Goodbye.
[DOOR BUZZES]
[♪♪♪]
[ALARM BEEPING]
Hey. Kim.
Can I talk to you?
-Sure, Ernie. What's going on?
-Uh....
Mr. McGill fired me.
-Why? What happened?
-I don't....
It doesn't matter.
I just....
Is Jimmy okay?
I feel bad, like it's my fault.
-I didn't mean for this to happen.
-What happened to Jimmy?
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
MAN: McGill.
-Yeah.
You're up.
JUDGE:
We've got CR-2003113081.
James McGill.
JIMMY:
Yes, Your Honor.
Not how I'm used to
seeing you in here, Mr. McGill.
-Not how I'd like to be seen.
-Wow.
You had quite the day yesterday.
Okay, Mr. McGill.
You've been accused of fourth degree
felony breaking and entering...
...which carries
a maximum sentence of 18 months...
...and a $5000 fine.
We've also got
petty misdemeanor assault.
Maximum six months jail time
and a $500 fine.
Plus, criminal damage to property.
Also misdemeanor with a maximum
sentence of six months and a $500 fine.
Victim is...
...your brother, Charles. Seriously?
I assume you're prepared
to enter a plea at this time.
Yes, Your Honor.
I wish to enter a plea of not guilty.
The court accepts and enters
the defendant's plea of not guilty.
Now, Mr. McGill,
have you secured counsel?
Yes, Your Honor. Kim Wexler, I'll be
representing Mr. McGill in this matter.
Just in time. Let's enter Ms. Wexler
as the attorney of record--
Your Honor, if I may,
I'll be representing myself.
I strongly advise against that,
Mr. McGill.
You know what they say
about a man who represents--
I'm-- I'm aware, but, as you know...
...I've defended many people
in the system.
Your Honor, may I have a moment
with my client?
Sounds like he's not your client.
Mr. McGill, would you like to
take a moment to discuss this with your...
...potential counsel?
No, Your Honor, I'm all set.
I'm gonna represent myself.
-Your Honor.
-Not your client, Ms. Wexler.
Sorry, moving on. You two
can work this out on your own time.
I was gonna call you,
but then I thought I'd tell you in person.
JUDGE:
Mr. McGill.
So on to the issue of bond.
You have no priors
and no outstanding warrants.
And where are
you currently practicing law?
I haven't seen you
in my court in a while.
Elder law.
What a noble pursuit.
One I hope you get back to very soon.
Given your ties to the community,
I see no reason to deny you bond.
Which I set now at $2500.
I fucked up.
Chuck bamboozled me again.
That tape? He made sure that
Ernie heard it, right?
Because he knew Ernie, bless him,
would tell me about it...
...and I'd come over,
try to destroy it or steal it or whatever.
Howard was there, and a PI.
If you can believe that.
Just waiting for me to lose my shit
and bust in.
Chuck played me like a fiddle,
and schmuck that I am, I fell for it.
Moron.
I'm sorry.
Then I didn't call you, which is stupid,
and sorry about that too.
But I didn't call you for a reason, okay?
Because this is my screw-up.
I own it, okay?
It's my responsibility to fix it.
And I know you wanna help, of course
you do, 'cause you're wonderful.
But...
...you're up to your ears in Mesa Verde,
and I can't, I won't, load this onto you too.
We have worked too hard
to let Chuck's bullshit vendetta...
...threaten everything we're building.
I won't allow him
to endanger our business, no.
I will fix this.
Myself, me, Jimmy McGill, okay?
You have gotta let me do this
on my own.
Okay.
Thank you.
I, um-- I finished it.
I-- I mean, I just touched up the edges...
...a little.
Is-- Is that okay?
Oh....
Uh, sure.
It looks nice.
You mind driving me to my car?
Sure, no problem.
Um....
Just so you know...
...this isn't a typical week around here.
Yeah, totally.
I didn't think that it was.
[IN SPANISH]
Good.
Aah.
Very good.
Uh-huh.
How long has he had the fever?
[IN SPANISH]
Three days.
Good.
Heart and lungs sound good.
No redness in his throat.
So I don't think it's strep.
You think if we ask mama nicely...
...she'll let you have this?
-Hm?
-Yes.
Very good. Bye.
What's left?
[IN SPANISH] Some stomach cramps,
sinus infection, and a possible ankle sprain.
What about the gringo?
The revenge.
I'll take him next.
[IN ENGLISH]
Mr. Clark.
The doctor's ready.
DOCTOR [IN ENGLISH]: And how
may I help you today, Mr. Clark?
I believe
our mutual acquaintance called ahead.
He told me what...
-...but not how much.
-Mm.
Well, I need a package...
...yea big.
And what's that in grams?
I don't know. This big.
Hey.
Is somebody sitting here?
No.
So how was it?
How was what?
Your night in MDC.
-I caught up with a few old clients.
-Yeah? Heh.
-Want one?
-Oh.
Yeah, this whole thing is...
-...a big misunderstanding.
-Mm-hm.
There's absolutely no way
it's going to trial.
Who wants that hassle?
Not me.
Whichever lucky soul
at the DA's office catches this...
...looking at an easy clear.
There's a felony in there, right?
Well, it'd be a cla-- Go ahead.
Classic case of overcharging.
No offense.
Happy to have a civil conversation,
and I'm always ready to make a deal.
Just call me Monty Hall.
So you're looking to plea out
on this then, Monty?
If it's the right plea.
I'm not perfect. I made mistakes,
I'm willing to own up to them...
...in a way that is satisfying
to both myself and the state.
Mm-hm. Well, good luck with that.
Good luck with that, as in,
"I wish you well"...
...or "I accept your challenge"?
I wish you well.
Play your cards right, they may go for it.
They?
Not you?
Prosecuting your case?
No, man, it's not me.
You never catch a lucky break, do you?
-Bad timing?
-No, conflicted out.
Conflicted out?
I mean, I figured that'd happen.
You and I have wheeled and dealed
together too many times.
There's no way
the boss was letting me run that one.
It's not Ericsen, is it?
The whole Albuquerque office is out.
We all know you, Jimmy.
Well, who is it?
I don't know.
They're pulling someone in from Belen.
Um, "Hay"?
Something Hay, I think.
I don't know. Boss used the words,
"tough but fair."
Gotta jam. Heh, heh.
Good luck.
Burger's getting cold. Heh.
You want it?
-Yeah?
-There's too many trans fats.
Those are the best fats.
-So they let you keep the car?
-What?
Davis and Main.
They let you keep the German car?
No.
That blows.
Ms. Hay?
Mr. McGill?
Chuck, please.
Meet me at the front door.
They said to put my things in the mailbox.
Yes, please. Anything with a battery.
Did your brother
ever have a key to the house?
Before the recent trouble, he did.
He brought me my groceries
and sundries.
But we had a falling out.
I have an employee
who does all that now.
You took away your brother's key
when you hired this employee?
I changed the locks.
Going-- Going back to the confrontation,
so I have it absolutely clear...
...did he strike you?
No, nothing like that.
He backed me into a cabinet.
Did he have a weapon?
Well, as I mentioned, he used
a fireplace poker to break into my desk.
But he never would've used it on me.
Did you feel physically threatened?
My brother is a lot of things,
but even he has limits.
And you're willing to appear
as a witness, even though he's family?
Unfortunately, yes.
If we continue with this...
...I'll need your sworn testimony.
I've had situations
involving family members before...
...where the injured party
has ultimately been reluctant...
...to cooperate with my office.
That won't happen.
I'm curious about your strategy.
Well...
...as officers of the court...
...I feel we should be held
to a higher standard.
I don't intend to take it easy on
your brother because he's a lawyer.
Of course not.
The bone of contention is
the felony breaking and entering.
He's gonna wanna
plea down to a misdemeanor...
...but I'll hold the line on the felony.
Which means
this could possibly go to trial.
Now, I-- I wanna be mindful
of your comfort and well-being.
With-- With your condition,
are you able to appear before the court?
-In person?
-I certainly appreciate...
...you accommodating me today
by coming here.
But don't worry, I'm able to tolerate
being out for short periods...
...with a few minor adjustments.
Nothing that will
overly inconvenience the court.
I'll get started on this.
Unless you have other concerns?
I just--
I just keep thinking....
-You know, Jimmy has a good heart.
-I'm-- I'm sure he does.
It's not an excuse for what he's done.
But he's my brother.
And I know....
Well, he--
Well, he's emotional,
he flies off the handle.
This is more than flying off the handle.
I'm not going to defend his actions...
...but I can't help wondering
if there's not a better solution...
...for everyone.
[♪♪♪]
[GUNSHOT]
[IN SPANISH]
What do you think?
Maybe hunters?
[GUNSHOT]
Maybe.
Hunters.
[GUNSHOT]
[CHATTERING]
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[WHINING]
[♪♪♪]
[IN ENGLISH]
Looks like we got a hit.
[SIRENS WAILING]
OFFICER:
Get down on your knees.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
Jesus, how old is this?
I found it in the glove box.
Best guess?
-From back when all the doors matched.
-Heh.
I got a deal offer from the ADA today.
And?
It's not what I expected.
Bad not what you expected?
It's just that...
...it's different.
She's offering me
pre-prosecution diversion.
Seriously?
A PPD?
That's great, Jimmy.
-Best I could hope for, right?
-Right.
What does she want you to confess to?
All of it.
The felony B and E.
Misdemeanor petty assault
and property damage.
I never touched him,
but they got assault in there.
Well, could be worse.
As long as they never activate it,
it doesn't matter, right?
You gonna be able to
keep your nose clean for a whole year?
Keep Viktor with a K on lockdown?
It's not a problem, Giselle.
And if I don't, it's instant jail, right?
Lucky break.
She must not want the hassle of a trial.
Guess so.
Jimmy.
This is good news.
And Chuck is gonna be pissed.
It's a big check in the pro column.
Actually, the PPD was Chuck's idea.
Shit.
Yeah.
What's his game?
One condition of the PPD
is that my written confession...
...is immediately submitted to
the New Mexico Bar Association.
Your written felony confession.
I thought he wanted me in jail,
he just wants my law license.
[SIGHS]
What are you gonna do?
Well...
...I knew the bar
was gonna be an issue, right?
So I figured I'd plea down
to a couple misdemeanors.
Get a censure
and maybe a little suspension.
But a confession to a felony?
Grounds for disbarment.
Yeah, and if I take it to trial and I lose...
...I face the bar anyways,
and jail time, most likely.
He's got me boxed in.
You can fight this.
The board listens to
extenuating circumstances--
No, Chuck knows everybody at the bar.
Hell, he made half their careers.
It's gonna be
him and his cronies versus me.
Alone.
Not alone.
-Kim.
-Come on, Jimmy.
You need me.
You can't argue this yourself.
You and I both know that, and I'm not
gonna let you fight this on your own.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Because I don't....
Why would you...?
Come on.
This guy? Seriously?
Let's just call it the fallacy of sunk costs.
So, what now?
Now?
Now we take that PPD
and we shove it right up Chuck's ass.
[♪♪♪]