[IN SPANISH]
You're back!
Hector!
HECTOR [IN SPANISH]:
Don Eladio.
Good, tell me.
What's your big news?
I bought a company.
ELADIO:
Yes?
What kind of company?
Ice cream.
A beautiful factory in Michoacan.
Ximenez here, he was their driver.
Immigration waves him through every time.
[IN SPANISH]
Don Eladio, it's a pleasure.
Idiot, you don't talk unless spoken to.
Ximenez.
Nice to meet you.
Tell me something, it wouldn't occur
to you to run off with our stuff.
No. Never.
No, no, no.
Just teasing!
[ELADIO LAUGHING]
But with this one, you better be careful.
You had better behave.
Because he gives no second chances.
Understand?
XIMENEZ: Yes, sir.
What else?
A store, an ice cream shop in Albuquerque.
Named it after you.
"The Winking Greek."
What is that?
[CHUCKLING]
What is this?
Is that supposed to be me?
Whoa. Sabrosito.
He's winking.
Ximenez, what do you say?
Does that look like me?
I don't....
No, of course not.
Because it's very fat, right?
Yes.
-Very chubby. I'm not that fat.
-No.
Eh? Very chubby.
So just the toy?
Ah!
That I like!
Go on....
Hey, Bolsa!
Son of a bitch!
[IN SPANISH]
Don Eladio, so good to see you!
It's good, it's good.
Hector.
Bolsa.
What did you bring?
Nothing much.
Such fancy wrapping. Whoa.
A t-shirt?
Ahh. Ha-ha!
Los Pollos Hermanos.
Very nice, Bolsa.
Look, Hector!
Pollos Hermanos.
More like the Butt Brothers.
[ELADIO CHUCKLES]
[WHISTLES]
BOLSA:
Over here!
ELADIO:
What is this?
BOLSA:
Over there.
ELADIO:
What is this?
Wow.
Gustavo sends his regards.
All of this from only one month?
He's a distribution genius.
See, Hector?
So neat and tidy.
I insist, from now on,
everyone must bring it like this.
No more rubber bands.
He wanted to come himself,
pay his respects.
He promises soon.
Let him stay.
And keep doing whatever he's doing.
What do you think, Hector?
Look what Gustavo gave us.
It's impressive, no?
It's okay.
"It's okay."
It seems to me
someone is a little jealous.
Mmm.
What's that you say, Sabrosito?
About Don Hector?
No.
Sabrosito tells me
Gustavo's is bigger than yours.
Don't be like that.
No, say something nice, Sabrosito, please.
What? What?
Yes.
You see.
Sabrosito says that yours is cute.
What? Is cute not good enough for you?
Hector, you're so serious. Very serious!
We're all friends here.
Let's go.
There is plenty of business
to do in the north.
Come.
Now then.
We'll eat some lunch.
Drink to your little shop.
Not a bad day's work, eh?
It's a good shirt, eh?
BOLSA:
It fits well.
ELADIO:
Inside, inside.
BOLSA:
Hector.
You coming?
Don't insult him.
What're you looking at?
[♪♪♪]
[POLICEMAN CHATTERING]
MAN 1: Does he have a truck yet?
MAN 2: No, but they're listening.
[KEYPAD BEEPS
AND LINE RINGING]
STACEY [OVER PHONE]: Pop?
-Hey, honey.
Almost didn't recognize the number.
I'm sorry. They changed my hours up at work.
I'm still getting used to it.
How are you two?
We're great.
Did it go okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Thanks to those movers you got,
all I had to do was watch.
And, Pop, this house....
Heh.
-It's good?
-It's great.
Kaylee loves her new school.
The neighborhood's friendly.
We feel safe.
That's good.
Mike, I don't know how to thank you.
Well, you don't have to.
I'm just glad you're enjoying it.
Do you want to come over for dinner?
-Tonight?
-Sure, I'm making lasagna.
There'll be plenty.
That's sweet,
but I don't want to put you out.
KAYLEE:
Pop-pop, come over.
STACEY:
There's someone here who wants to see you.
Ice cream.
Oh, is she snoozing?
Close.
Ice cream?
I should have let well enough alone.
I'm good.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
I'll have his.
No. I don't think so.
MAN 1 [ON TV]: Maybe we can get a lift.
MAN 2: Yeah.
Hey!
MAN 1: What's the matter?
MAN 2: Some guys, hanging around the truck.
MAN 1: Air-raid warden?
MAN 2: No, funny-looking guys.
MAN 1: What do you mean, "funny looking"?
MAN 2: I mean funny looking.
Like fish.
MAN 1: Who are you kidding?
What do you mean, "like fish"?
MAN 2: They got scales.
-Hey.
You okay?
Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
MAN 1:
Off a flying saucer! Off a Sputnik!
WOMAN:
Oh, look, they've seen us!
MAN 1: Let's get out of here!
WOMAN: Things from outer space.
MAN 2:
Off a flying saucer!
[CHATTERING]
MAN 1:
Hot sauce?
[GRUNTS]
I can't have pico de gallo.
I'm really sorry about that.
Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
May I take your order?
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Oh, men's room is on the left.
[IN ENGLISH]
Cabron, I need to see your boss.
Okay, well, I'm the assistant manager.
The manager's actually not here today.
HECTOR:
Not the manager. The boss.
-You mean Mr. Fring?
-Mr. Fring.
Well, he's not here at the moment. I'm sure
I could help you with whatever you need.
I need Fring.
Well, like I said he's not here,
and I don't really know when he'll be back.
I can take a message.
I'll wait.
You don't have to do that.
I'd be happy to take a message.
I'm sure Mr. Fring wouldn't want
to keep you waiting.
Okay, sir, if you don't mind,
there are other customers.
Jeez, sorry about that.
Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
-May I take your order?
MAN 2: Yeah, can I get a 12-piece bucket...
...with jumbo fries...
...and--
-You said the 12-piece?
MAN 2: Yeah, the 12-piece.
Excuse me, sir? You can't light that in here.
Sir?
There's no smoking on the premises.
[♪♪♪]
Please, sir, look at the signs. No fumar.
You can't-- It's--
It's a health code violation.
-Sir, it's employees only.
-We have to go, okay?
Let's go.
Sir?
Sir, you're not allowed back here.
Gus Fring is a pillar
of our local business community.
Not just for underwriting
our travel raffle...
...but for making the best damn chicken
in town.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
-Gus.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Well, gentlemen, ladies, I hope to never
need your services, no offense.
But if I ever did, it's good to know that....
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
Yes?
I'll be right there.
I want you all to go home now.
You will be compensated for your full shifts.
Normal schedule tomorrow.
Go, now.
We are closed for today.
Mr. Fring, you sure you want
to be left with these guys?
I'm fine, Lyle. You go home.
Should I call someone?
No.
That will not be necessary, truly.
You sure?
Please do as I ask.
I'll see you tomorrow.
NACHO:
He's waiting in the office.
I know where he is.
Don Hector.
Took you long enough.
Don Hector...
...mine is a cartel business.
But...
...it is mine.
And it is legitimate.
My employees are civilians.
Your actions here today
have endangered them...
...my interests, and those of the cartel.
I am the cartel.
And from now on, you are my mule.
You are going to bring my product north.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
I understand that your supply line
has been compromised.
And this is most unfortunate.
However, my trucks...
...are already at maximum capacity.
Make room.
Don Hector. You must understand
that I answer to Juan Bolsa.
You want to cry to Bolsa?
Cry to Bolsa.
Or, hell, Eladio.
Adding more product will threaten
the reliability of the entire operation.
May I ask...
...did Don Eladio approve this?
I approve this.
You're doing it.
[DOOR OPENS]
You gonna let me out of here?
Hello?
Tell him we're square.
What?
No.
Excuse me, everyone.
Could you all please take a moment
and join me out here?
Please, come.
Come, come, come.
I would--
I would like to apologize
to each and every one of you...
...who, yesterday, had to endure
the behavior of those men.
It was unacceptable.
Despite the difficult circumstances...
...you all acquitted yourselves impeccably.
That said...
...if any of you wish to seek counseling
due to lingering trauma...
...speak with me privately
and it will be arranged.
Also, you will all be receiving 24 hours
of overtime...
...as I am sure in one way or another...
...each of you brought
this incident home with you.
Yes, Lyle?
LYLE:
Mr. Fring...
...who were those guys?
Well, as some of you know...
...many years ago...
...I opened my first Los Pollos Hermanos
in Michoacan.
Shortly thereafter...
...those same men showed up.
They wanted money.
And I--
I'm--
I'm ashamed to say that...
...I paid them.
You see, in that place, at that time...
...if I wished to conduct my business,
I had no choice.
But yesterday....
Yesterday, they came here.
Here.
They intimidated my customers.
They threatened my employees.
And again...
...they wanted money.
Now, my friends...
...I must confess...
...that I almost gave them what they wanted.
But then, I thought, "No."
No.
This is America.
Here, the righteous have no reason to fear.
Here, those men have no power.
And when they saw
that I had no fear of them...
...they ran, like the cowards they are,
back across the border.
They will not return.
We will move on from this.
My friends...
...I promise you...
...that together...
...we will prosper.
All right.
Yes, hi. I'm still here.
Really? Uh.... You sure--
Sure. Gotcha.
Sorry for bothering you.
Hi, I'm calling because we had an appointment
with you guys for...
...I think Wednesday? Heh.
I'll be honest with you,
I can barely read my own darn handwriting.
My mistake.
Okay. Have a nice day.
Hello, I'm calling to confirm an appointment
for Charles McGill.
Yes, it's 215 San Cristobal Road.
McGill, with an M.
A door.
Okay, I thought it was you guys.
Guess I was wrong.
Thanks anyway.
Hi, I'm calling about an appointment
for Charles McGill.
Well, that's why I'm calling.
I think it's for this week, but--
Good thing my head's attached to my neck.
San Cristobal, that's right.
Yes, that's it.
Two-thirty tomorrow?
Great.
So we're gonna need to cancel that.
Yeah.
I will.
Thank you.
Bye.
Oh, poor Frisky.
Well, Pomeranians can be difficult.
All that hair.
I know.
So, Mrs. Vallance, does Thursday 11:30 work?
That's right, 11:30. I'll make sure....
No.
Really?
Martin's Handyman and Repair,
2:30 tomorrow.
Thank you. How many calls did that take?
I lost track. Is that it?
Yeah, I'm nearly done. I'm just...
...giving it a remorse pass.
Remorse is important.
"Destroyed property."
I'd try "damaged" the victim's property...
...instead of "destroyed."
See if you can't get away with that.
Yeah.
Boom.
Yeah, that's nice.
I mean it, by the way.
What?
Thank you.
Seriously.
You're welcome, seriously.
I better get back to it.
Yeah.
Are you--?
You're...
...absolutely sure
you got the right guy for this?
Um....
The crème de la crème.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Martin's Repair?
-Yeah. Mr. McGill?
-Good afternoon.
If you don't mind wiping your shoes.
It's this way.
Mind the step here.
As you'll see, the frame is boarded over...
...but the door itself is intact.
The damage is mainly
to the door jamb and casing.
There's another step up here.
MIKE: Oh.
CHUCK: Mm-hm.
MIKE:
Break-in?
CHUCK:
That's right.
Went after your copper wire,
from the look of it.
There was a time, remember,
when we could leave our doors unlocked.
I certainly do.
Yeah.
-Where do I plug in?
-You don't.
-No?
-No. Didn't you--?
I believe my assistant was very clear
with your dispatcher.
No electricity due to a condition
that was explained...
...in some detail.
[WHIRRING]
No problem.
Good thing I charged my battery.
I'd be going at it
like Fred Flintstone otherwise.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I understood there would
be no power tools of any kind.
What, a screwdriver and a hammer?
Turns a morning job into two days...
...with me, myself and Bengay.
But it's your call.
I suppose.
Very well.
[DRILL WHIRRING]
You seem to be making fast work of it.
Good.
It's good.
Um.... Okay, what I'll do, I think, is....
[WHIRRING CONTINUES
INTERMITTENTLY]
JIMMY:
Heh. Very good.
Yeah.
Nice.
Great.
Yep. Nice.
At some point, we should probably
discuss the rule of thirds...
...but otherwise, these....
Oh, wow.
A gas lantern sitting on a stack
of frigging Financial Times.
Now, that tells a whole story.
These are museum-quality.
You, my friend, are the Ansel Adams
of covert photography.
And that other thing?
How'd you get it?
Address book on his desk.
Right.
So...
...what'd you think of him?
I mean, speak freely.
You couldn't possibly offend me.
He's a bit of a prick, right?
Nothing?
Seriously?
All right.
Can't even dish the dirt with this guy.
Isn't our business concluded?
Yeah. Even Steven.
-I mean, you did fix the door, right?
-Yeah.
You did a reasonably good job of it?
Otherwise--
He won't be grumbling to anyone.
That's all I'm asking.
I did it right.
Thank you.
Nice to fix something for once.
Well, if that's how you feel
I've got a leaky toilet back at the office.
All right.
If you ever need anything from my end....
Hasta luego.
WAITRESS: Here you go.
CUSTOMER: Thanks.
May we talk?
You can park it over there.
You sent back the payment we agreed upon.
What I did, I didn't do for you.
The man.
The one killed for helping the truck driver.
If I may make an observation...
...perhaps you were trying to correct
something which cannot be corrected.
It's not the kind of thing
I want to take money for.
But the fact remains...
...that your actions benefited me
more than you can know.
That's your business.
I'm just glad to have Salamanca
out of my head.
Well, perhaps in the future...
...you will consider working for me.
[♪♪♪]
Could be.
That'd depend on the work.
Would you care to know why...
...I stopped you from killing Hector?
Like you said, it wasn't in your interest.
A bullet to the head
would have been far too humane.
Jimmy.
Howard.
HOWARD: Kim.
-Chuck.
Kim.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Good afternoon.
Oh.
Good.
-Mr. McGill, does this work for you?
-It'll have to do.
Thank you.
I assume everyone left their cell phones
and so on at reception.
HOWARD:
Yes, indeed.
And you'll let me know
if you need a break or anything else.
CHUCK:
I will. Thank you, Ms. Hay.
Well...
...I was actually speaking
to my husband about your condition.
CHUCK:
Oh, yes?
I had an aunt. She's no longer with us.
She went to church every Sunday, but...
...when the boys' choir sang,
she would absolutely have to leave.
Something about the frequency of their voices
really did a number on her.
-Well, that is a shame.
-Indeed.
All right.
Let's get down to it.
We are here to finalize the pre-prosecution
diversion for James Morgan McGill.
Representing the divertee,
Ms. Kimberly Wexler.
Mr. James McGill has signed a contract...
...waiving his rights to a speedy trial...
...and presentment of his case
within the statute of limitations.
The terms of the deal are for you, James...
...to report to your pre-prosecution
service officer...
...at the Albuquerque
District Attorney's Office...
...on the second Monday of every month
for the next 12 months.
Community service hours will be assigned.
You must maintain lawful employment.
You must only associate
with law-abiding citizens.
Your client understands that
if he violates the terms of the agreement...
...or is arrested for any infraction...
...the crimes to which he's confessed will be
prosecuted to the full extent of the law...
-...in addition to any new charges.
-He understands.
And I must inform you, Mr. McGill,
as an officer of the court...
...and member of the bar...
...your confession will be referred
to the New Mexico Bar Association.
Okay, I have your statement here.
Has everyone had a chance to read it?
Comments? Thoughts?
Actually, page two.
He "damaged the victim's property."
Would it not be more accurate to say
"destroyed a cassette tape"?
I'm sorry.
Wasn't the cassette tape his property?
-Of course.
-Then it seems accurate...
...to say he damaged the victim's property.
Why be vague?
And "damaged" doesn't reflect
its irrevocable condition.
-"Damaged property belonging to the victim."
CHUCK: It was a cassette tape.
That's what it was.
Not a teacup. Not a chair.
A cassette tape.
[WHISPERS]
"Destroyed item of personal property"?
CHUCK:
All right.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] We'd suggest
"destroyed item of personal property."
Ms. Wexler?
Works for us.
Shall I change it, or--?
If you would.
"Destroyed item of personal property."
There.
HAY:
Can you initial it, please?
J-M-M.
Initialed.
Charles, was there anything else you found
wanting in your brother's statement?
No.
We're satisfied. Thank you.
All right, so we're all set?
No, not all set, Mr. McGill.
Your brother may be satisfied, but I am not.
The confession you've written is adequate,
but frankly, I sense a lack of remorse.
And I, for one,
would like to hear an apology.
Charles deserves at least that much.
Uh....
-Now?
-Yes, Mr. McGill, now.
Okay.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I was wrong--
Mr. McGill, could you at least
look your brother in the eye?
Chuck...
...I'm very sorry.
I lost my temper and I did some things...
...so many things that I regret.
I shouldn't have broken down your door.
Doesn't matter how I was provoked.
I shouldn't have done that.
There's no excuse for that...
...or for the things that I said.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I regret it all.
All of it, more than you can imagine...
...because--
Because you're my brother...
...and no one should treat
his own brother like that.
Not ever.
Okay?
HAY:
All right, then.
On to the matter of restitution.
Mr. McGill, according to your agreement,
you have two weeks to pay your brother--
I would like to pay up now, if I may?
HAY:
You may.
The amount is $321.
Uh, Ms. Hay, I'm sorry.
That figure doesn't represent
a full accounting.
-Oh, no?
-I believe the correct amount is $323.98.
That includes the cassette tape...
...which was destroyed.
HAY:
Good. Thank you.
Three hundred twenty-three dollars
and 98 cents...
...including the cassette tape.
What do you say we get you home?
Howard. Chuck.
I'm putting you both on notice
regarding the bar hearing.
First, I'm filing a motion
to suppress that tape.
The tape that Jimmy destroyed, you mean.
How about we stop with the games?
No way there isn't a duplicate.
Really?
Of course there is.
You knew Jimmy was gonna break in.
You wanted him to.
There's no way you'd let him destroy
the only copy. You made a duplicate.
-It's the first thing you did.
-Kim.
This is not how we do discovery.
Actually, Jimmy destroyed the duplicate.
Uh, it's fine, Howard.
The original is under lock and key, and
in due time, it will be put into evidence...
...for your review.
So, of course, file whatever motions
you'd like. It's your privilege.
-I will. Count on it.
-But, Kim...
...you should be aware, because I believe
this'll be your first disciplinary hearing...
...the Bar Association's standard of proof
is far more lenient than what you're used to.
Motions aside, that tape will be played.
Chuck?
See you, Kim.
Well?
What?
Bingo.
[♪♪♪]