[LATIN MUSIC PLAYING]
You're good.
See you, Nacho.
Don Hector.
Mm.
Hola, Don Hector.
Hey, Nacho.
NACHO:
Have a seat.
DOMINGO:
How's your dad?
Uh, fine.
-Business good?
-Yeah, I think so.
-Cool.
-All right.
Hey, my father's gonna
bring in his Corolla.
His dogs tore up the back seat.
Like, ate the stuffing.
So one of my guys, new kid,
got spooked by a cruiser and ran.
Dumped his stash in the gutter.
Let me finish.
You're light.
-Like I was saying, the guy--
-Why didn't you make it up on your end?
I did, but I couldn't make it all up.
You got my share, man.
I swear.
All right. Make it up next week.
Thank you, Nacho.
Don Hector.
Who works for who, huh?
[SIGHS]
DOMINGO:
Nacho, no.
No!
Oh, come on. Come on.
[SCREAMING]
No! No, I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
No, no--
Nacho. [SCREAMS]
[CLATTERING]
[BLOWS LANDING
AND DOMINGO GROANING]
[SEWING MACHINE WHIRRING]
[IN SPANISH]
Son.
Have you seen the black cowhide?
[IN SPANISH]
In the back, Dad.
On the top shelf.
Next to the red suede.
Oh.
[♪♪♪]
[SEWING STOPS]
[MAN TALKING IN SPANISH
OVER TV]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE OVER TV]
[♪♪♪]
KIM: I wanna start by thanking you
for your patience...
...through this long
and emotional proceeding.
Jimmy McGill has worked tirelessly...
...to build a practice
that helps an underserved...
...and frankly, overlooked segment
of our community...
...the elderly.
You've heard from many
of Mr. McGill's clients today.
Every one of them came here gladly
in support of their lawyer.
Jimmy reached out to people...
...who may never have seen an attorney
in their entire lives.
He took the time to make sure
they had wills...
...that accurately reflected their wishes
for a price they could afford.
Because Jimmy McGill
cares about people.
He's devoted the past three years
of his life to his brother's welfare.
Waking at 5 in the morning
to buy Charles' favorite newspaper...
...from the single newsstand
in the city that carries it.
Dropping everything to care for his
brother through multiple hospitalizations.
Even supporting Charles' career...
...by hand-making
a Mylar-lined suit jacket...
...to spare his brother discomfort
from exposure to electricity.
And yet, during this time...
...Charles McGill's irrational animus
towards his brother...
...grew to epic proportions.
So when Jimmy discovered that Charles
had used his love and his caring...
...against him...
...when he discovered...
...he had been betrayed
by his only living blood relative...
...Jimmy snapped.
Wouldn't you?
I might.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Chuck?
KIM: Jimmy McGill understands
he broke the law...
...when he forced his way
into his brother's house...
...and he is deeply sorry.
He is more than ready
to face the consequences.
However,
as to ethical violation 16-304A...
...the state bar's claim
of destruction of evidence...
...it categorically did not happen.
Jimmy McGill had no agenda
when he entered his brother's home.
-He lost his temper, plain and simple.
-Chuck, please let me in.
So now the question you must
ask yourselves is this:
Is the legal profession better
with Jimmy McGill in it?
I believe the answer is a resounding yes.
Oh. Here's to 12 short months.
Also, somebody call the pope
because according to your summation...
...I ought to be a saint, me and
Mother Teresa, right up there with her.
"St. Jimmy."
Yeah, that has a nice ring to it.
Boom.
Ah.
So have you given any thought to what
you're gonna do for the next year?
-You know, with your clients?
-Whoa.
Slow down.
That is tomorrow talk, counselor.
Tonight, I celebrate with
the world's best defense attorney.
Where are your notes?
Let's spread them out and roll around
on them. See what happens.
[LAUGHING]
It's a good plan.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Rebecca?
REBECCA:
Jimmy.
JIMMY:
Well, I'm-- Come on in, please.
-Hi. Uh, Kim Wexler.
-Rebecca Bois.
We didn't formally meet earlier.
-Right. It's nice to meet you.
REBECCA: Yeah.
I was just at Chuck's,
and he won't answer the door.
I was out there knocking
for almost an hour.
That sounds like Chuck. I'm sure
he's fine. He's just being dramatic.
I think it's a little bit more than that.
I want you to come with me
to get him to let us in.
-Jimmy, he needs our help.
-No, thanks.
I've already kicked my door in
for the year.
You owe it to him.
I don't owe him squat.
Jimmy, you lied to me.
This was never about helping Chuck.
If you feel misled, I apologize,
but I think I was clear.
I told you I had to defend myself...
...and Chuck would need help afterwards,
which he does.
You got what you wanted.
Now it's time to do what's right.
Yeah....
No.
Jimmy, he's still your brother.
Not anymore, he's not.
Chuck was right about you all along.
He's mentally ill. What is your excuse?
Enjoy your champagne.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Like the other night, during dinner...
...Kaylee asked if her daddy
ever used to cook.
And I told her about...
...how Matty used to make her
Mickey Mouse pancakes on weekends.
You know, two small pancake ears
attached to a big one?
She didn't remember,
but I think it made her happy.
She even asked for them
the next morning.
Boy, Matty made it look easy.
Keeping the ears separated,
it's really hard.
Mine looked terrible,
but Kaylee didn't care.
Now she wants "Daddy pancakes"
every weekend.
[WOMAN CHUCKLES]
But there are times....
Career day's coming up...
...and she asked me if I would go
and talk about her daddy's job.
She wants to know
more about what he did.
That kind of took my breath away.
Kaylee's teacher thinks
it would be good for her...
...maybe make his absence feel
a little bit more normal.
MAN: So do you think you're gonna do it?
-I don't know.
-Maybe.
MAN: Good.
That's good work, Stacey.
Well, who's next?
STACEY:
Thanks for coming. It means a lot.
MIKE: Well, honey, if it makes you
feel any better, I'm all for it.
STACEY:
Enough that you'd come again?
MIKE:
We'll see.
STACEY: Well, the thing is I sort of
volunteered you for something.
MIKE: What?
-To help with the new playground.
The kids deserve way better
than that, don't you think?
Sure, but why me?
Well, they need someone who
knows how to pour concrete.
The slide and swings need
something called footings, I think.
Sweetheart,
that's not really my department.
Sure it is, Pop.
You built a carport when Matty was a kid.
I did?
Yeah, he told me about it
a bunch of times.
He said when
you were pricing it out...
...you thought all the people
who gave you quotes were crooks.
So you decided to do it yourself.
And you let Matty write his initials
in the wet cement.
Pop, the way he talked about you,
it was like you hung the moon.
I'm sorry.
I can get you out of it. I thought--
No, it's fine.
Just tell me when and where.
-Ha-ha-ha.
-Come on. Jeez.
STACEY:
Thank you.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Chuck?
Chuck, it's Howard.
[KNOCKING]
I'm not leaving, Chuck.
I don't want to wake up the neighbors,
but I got all night.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Chuck?
That is a 35-year-old Macallan.
I'm not gonna tell you
how much it cost...
...but don't worry,
it's coming out of my end.
The opinion came in.
Jimmy was suspended
for 12 months.
This is a win, my friend.
I know, it doesn't feel like it.
But hear me out.
Jimmy's not gonna be
a lawyer for one year.
And if he screws up,
which we both know is likely...
...his PPD terminates.
And that one year
may turn into forever.
Chuck, you're at a crossroads.
You can keep looking backwards...
...stay focused on your brother,
what he's up to, or you can go forward.
And, Chuck, listen to me...
...Jimmy's just not worth it.
Where would we be if...
...say, Clarence Darrow had
devoted the best years of his life...
...to supervising his
ne'er-do-well relatives?
Think of the cases
he wouldn't have taken...
...the injustices that would
have gone unanswered.
What a waste.
I say...
...put your energy into the future.
Anything else...
...is a waste of your time and intellect.
What do you say?
[SNIFFS]
[EXHALES]
To new beginnings.
You okay to drive?
Absolutely.
How are you feeling?
Oh, I'm fine. Thank you, Howard.
[SIGHS]
[CAR DEPARTING]
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
Lunch is served.
Swim, honey.
Get it before it's soggy.
[SIGHS]
-Francesca, it's go time.
FRANCESCA: Where do you wanna start?
With the A's.
FRANCESCA: Hi, Mrs. Adamson?
It's Francesca at Jimmy McGill's office.
Are you available to talk with Jimmy?
Okay, great.
Mrs. Adamson.
Hello, dear. Do you have a moment?
I just wanted you
to be the first to know...
...that I'll be taking
a brief sabbatical from the law.
Just one year.
One quick trip of the Earth
around the sun and I'll be back.
I will.
[♪♪♪]
-Next.
FRANCESCA: Hold for Jimmy.
I did? Oh, that's an honor.
And how did he pass?
Next. The details will all be
in a letter you'll receive shortly.
Mostly legal boilerplate.
Now you give that nephew a hug for me.
Niece.
Next.
-Hold for Jimmy.
-It's just a technical thing, really.
It's just a technical--
An agreement. It's an agreement.
It's an agreement that I came to
with the bar association.
You're gonna get a letter
with all the details so--
Mr. Levine, can you hear me? Hello?
Can you hear me still?
Okay, you stop talking and I'll talk.
Okay. Next.
The letter will explain it, but the details
are boring, legalistic mumbo jumbo.
I don't know where those sounds
are coming from, sir.
You-- You'll have to check.
Well, then stay inside.
Details will be in a letter.
That's right, but don't worry about it.
Next. Next. Next. Next. Next.
Yes, Mrs. Pressman,
I still have the document.
I'm including the calico.
I don't wanna get down
into the weeds on this with you.
Just my headache, sir. I'm tired.
Listen to you. Where did you
learn so much about lawyering?
Yes, just watch your mail
for that letter from my office.
Okay. Bye bye.
-Next.
FRANCESCA: Last one. Mr. Yalowitz.
Last one.
Mr. Yalowitz. Hey, it's Jimmy McGill.
Listen, for your future lawyering needs,
I am taking a hiatus of one year.
Will you please watch your mail
for a letter from my office?
Yes, Jimmy from TV.
You watch it every day, huh?
Really?
Were you the pilot of the B-29?
Thirty-two missions? Holy--
Well, can I just say, sir...
...you are one of the people who made
the Greatest Generation so damn great.
I salute you.
All right. See you soon.
On TV, right.
Bye.
Francesca, get me KWBV.
Okay.
Get me the manager.
Then get me somebody
who can pull a commercial, stat.
-You finished making your calls?
-Yeah, that was a ton of fun.
Ahem. But what gets me is this.
What is it?
It is my KWBV contract.
I almost let one of my ads run today.
-You can't do that.
-I know.
But can you believe this?
I've got nine airings left.
I'm out 4000 bucks.
Whew.
I guess...
...you have to find a local business
and sell them your time.
-What else can you do?
-Ahem. Yeah.
This pile of garbage explicitly states
I'm not allowed to resell.
You're a lawyer.
See if you can you find a loophole.
I cannot look at another contract.
I'm up to my eyeballs in Mesa Verde.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
So, what do you want to do
about Francesca?
[CLEARS THROAT]
Do about her? What?
How much notice should we give her?
Two weeks?
We're not doing her any favors
by keeping her in the dark.
She should start looking.
[SCOFFS]
So you want to fire Francesca?
I don't want to.
I don't need her for more than filing
and getting coffee. I can do that myself.
We just hired her. I like her.
We need to talk about
the overhead on this place.
No, Kim, no.
This office is set up
for two legal practices...
...and now there's only one. I don't need
all this space. I only have one client.
-It's a huge client.
-I looked into it...
...and breaking the lease will cost
less than 10 months' rent.
We didn't go through all this to give up
everything after one day of suspension.
-One day.
-It's not everything.
It's an office. Four walls and a door.
Why waste money on something
we don't need?
As far as I'm concerned,
nothing's changed, all right?
I'll hold up my end,
you hold up yours. Fifty-fifty.
You'll keep paying for half a law office
even though you're not practicing law?
-Call it aspirational thinking.
-Okay.
But how are you gonna pay for it?
The day I don't show up with my half...
...that's the day we'll talk
about closing this place.
That's fair, I guess.
You'll see.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Look at the two of you.
I mean, you belong on TV.
You're naturals.
I know. You're thinking,
"It's too good to be true.
The TV's too expensive.
We can't afford that."
Well, I'm telling you, you can.
And here's the beauty part.
For a reasonable price,
we will shoot your commercial.
And then we'll throw in the air-time
for the low, low price of free.
"Hey, give me Jimmy."
That's right. That's me.
You've seen my ad.
Well, what I did for me,
my friends, I will do that for you.
Look,
our all-inclusive premium package...
...that's gonna be
the best bang for your buck.
We'll shoot nine commercials
for $4,900.
Okay?
And that includes the nine airings at 3:20
in the afternoon on channel KWBV.
That is a prime slot with a viewership...
...of tens of thousands
of potential customers.
-It does sound like a good deal.
-It does.
-It's a lot of money.
-Yeah.
That's perfectly understandable.
It's a big financial commitment.
That's why we have
our "Toe-in-the-Water" package.
That's one commercial,
flat rate, 849.95.
Beauty part again, free airtime.
And when this thing runs,
you're gonna get calls.
I can promise you that. Heh.
We'll think about it.
Excellent.
When do you think you might decide?
-Maybe next week.
-Yeah.
Oh. Gee, I'm sorry for any confusion.
But I was talk--
I was talking
about a much shorter window...
...for the thinking part.
How short?
We would have you on the air
by 3:20 this afternoon.
Today? You're gonna shoot a commercial
in the next two and a half hours?
Oh, no. I mean,
there's a whole post process.
There's editing,
and mixing, coloring, layback.
It's a whole megillah.
You don't want to know.
But we would need to be shooting
in the next 15 minutes.
WOMAN: No, there's Joseph and
the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat.
MAN 1: I thought they made,
like, a Moses musical.
MAN 2: They did.
WOMAN: They did.
MAN 1:
Which one's that? "Let my people go"?
MAN 2:
Well, yeah. It was kind of--
JIMMY:
Everybody get in the car.
-Is everything okay?
-No.
I air in two hours and 20 minutes,
and I have no client.
That's another 400 bucks
down the drain.
How do I find somebody who
needs a commercial and can afford one?
Maybe you could make a commercial.
Have you not been listening?
That's what I've been trying--
Oh.
Right.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
JIMMY:
Let's go. Chop chop.
All right. Uh....
Plant it right here.
I want you to get
those dishes behind me.
Hi, this is Jimmy McGill.
For a limited time-- No.
Jimmy McGill here to talk about
the wonders of broadcast-- No.
Jimmy McGill's the name.
Advertising is--
Camera ready.
Hi, I'm Jimmy McGill with an amazing
opportunity for small business owners--
Shit. No. I can't do this.
-Sure, you can.
-No.
We're totally off-brand here.
I'm Jimmy McGill,
a lawyer you can trust.
I can't suddenly turn into
commercial guy.
Hold on.
Repeat after me. For a limited time,
we'll shoot your commercial today...
...and have it on the air tomorrow.
For a limited time,
we'll shoot your commercial today...
...and have it on air tomorrow.
I thought you were president
of the Drama Club or something?
I'm treasurer.
You, go.
Say the words.
For a limited, uh, time,
uh, only we could--
Cut. Maybe next time.
Woof.
We gonna do this or not? Because
either way I'm getting my 100 bucks.
Quick, crack open your magic bag.
We'll have to Karloff this thing.
[♪♪♪]
All the same weight?
Within a quarter gram.
NACHO:
You have a scale?
[SCOFFS]
Take your pick.
You forgot how to count?
You get five.
Don Hector gets six.
He's expecting six.
And that's what I'm gonna bring.
He's trying to take six.
We only owe him five.
He's pushing it.
-Give it to him.
MAN: You sure?
Give it to him.
[♪♪♪]
Well?
It could work.
Okay, then.
[♪♪♪]
[SIREN WAILING]
[LINE RINGING]
WOMAN: Doctor's exchange.
-May I speak with Dr. Lara Cruz, please?
-Can you hold a moment?
-Yes, I'll hold.
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
[INHALES THEN CLEARS THROAT]
WOMAN: Thank you for your patience.
-Doctor--?
-Is this an emergency?
-I need to speak with her.
-Who's calling?
-Yeah, Charles McGill.
I'm a patient, former patient.
I need to see Dr. Cruz
as soon as possible.
-I'll page her. Please hold.
-Thank you.
[GASPS]
So?
I took the five, then one more.
What'd he say? Did he piss himself?
No, he wasn't there,
it was just his guys.
So, what happened?
They called him, and while we were
waiting to see what he'd say...
...one of the guys
put a gun to my head.
They put a gun to your head?
Mm-hm.
It's no big deal.
[PHONE RINGING]
Lionel.
Go outside. See what he found out.
Yeah.
[COUGHS]
So your father...
...his shop...
...where does he get his upholstery?
From, uh, the distributor.
And where is the distributor?
-Jalisco.
-Jalisco. Ah.
I want a new way
to get my stuff over the border.
A legitimate business.
Right, but the chicken man--
Temporary.
I want a new front, my own.
Don Hector,
my father is a simple man.
He is not in the business.
-You will teach him.
-Don Hector, please--
Don't worry. I'll take
good care of papi. He'll make money.
A lot more than with
his little sewing machine.
Lionel talked to our guy in Los Lunas.
Looks like Tuco knifed a guy.
He broke a guard's jaw.
They've got him in solitary.
What?
All he had to do was six months.
He'll be in there forever.
[HECTOR GRUNTS THEN WHEEZING]
Oh....
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
ARTURO:
Boss.
You talk to your father.
I promise,
as soon as you see the first one...
...you're gonna want
the whole package.
Uh-- Take about an hour.
So I'll bring the whole team down there.
We'll be there 12:30 sharp.
I'm gonna turn you into a star.
Absolutely, you'll be
on the air by tomorrow afternoon.
I know. It is amazing.
Okay, and don't wear stripes
because you'll moire.
It's a filmmaking term.
Just don't wear stripes.
Okay. See you then.
-You want a beer?
-Yes. Thanks.
So sleeping in your own bed tonight.
Things must be looking up.
I needed clean clothes.
What was all that?
-Well, I'm unloading that ad time.
-But I thought you couldn't sell it.
Well, that's the thing. I'm not.
They pay me to make a commercial.
I throw in the airtime for free.
-Smart.
-Yeah.
I spent most of the day going
door to door pitching. No dice.
Then it came to me. I'm selling
advertising. Why not advertise?
And it worked.
I mean, TV commercials get calls.
What commercial did you run?
Not-- Not "Gimme Jimmy"?
No, I-- I made a new one.
When?
Today.
Right here.
So you made a commercial
for commercials today?
Yeah, I'm starting to think
I might break even here.
[LAUGHS]
Okay. Let's see it.
I don't know.
It's not my best work.
It's very last minute.
Well, you're getting calls.
It can't be that bad.
Yeah.
What, now you're getting shy? Heh.
Come on.
Okay, but keep in mind--
Yeah, yeah, it's not your best work.
I got it.
What's that I see?
Albuquerque's next TV star?
It's you, small business owner.
Struggling to make it
in today's fast-paced economy?
Thought television advertising
was too expensive for you?
Well, you better think again.
You can't afford not to be on TV.
Look at you, you're a triple threat.
Great services,
great products, and most of all...
...that face. You're a star.
Wrap it all up in your natural charisma
and bam, you belong on TV.
Better watch out for
autograph hounds and paparazzi.
And it gets better.
I can have you on the air tomorrow.
You heard me right. Tomorrow.
Better get ready to be famous,
Albuquerque.
I can make you a TV star
for a price you can afford.
Call me, Saul Goodman.
The world needs to know
about you and your business.
Call me now.
The guy at the station said he's never
seen so many star wipes in a row.
It's never been done.
KIM:
Saul Goodman?
Yeah, it's like, "It's all good, man."
Heh.
-That guy has a lot of energy.
-Yeah.
It's just a name.
Huh.
[♪♪♪]