BOY: WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
MAN: DR. COCHRANE WOULD
BE PROUD OF YOU.
I KNOW THE WHOLE SPEECH
BY HEART.
WHEN'S IT GONNA BE READY TO FLY?
MAN: LET THE PAINT DRY FIRST.
NO, I MEAN YOUR SHIP.
MAN: NOT FOR A WHILE.
IT'S NOT EVEN BUILT YET.
YOU KNOW THAT.
HOW BIG WILL IT BE?
PRETTY BIG.
BIGGER THAN
AMBASSADOR POINTY'S SHIP?
HIS NAME IS SOVAL,
AND HE'S BEEN VERY HELPFUL,
AND I TOLD YOU NOT TO CALL HIM
THAT, JONATHAN.
WELL, BILLY COOK SAID WE'D
BE FLYING AT WARP 5 BY NOW
IF THE VULCANS HADN'T
KEPT THINGS FROM US.
MAN: WELL, THEY HAVE
THEIR REASONS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
GOD KNOWS WHAT THEY ARE.
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GUN CHARGES ]
MAN: DROP YOUR WEAPON.
I MEAN IT!
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
A WORD YOU'RE SAYING,
BUT I GUARANTEE YOU,
I KNOW HOW TO USE THIS.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
MAN: ♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
MAN: THE VENTRAL PLATING TEAM
SAYS THEY'LL BE DONE
IN ABOUT THREE DAYS.
BE SURE THEY MATCH THE COLOR
TO THE NACELLE HOUSINGS.
PLANNING TO SIT ON THE HULL
AND POSE FOR SOME POSTCARDS?
MAN: MAYBE.
MAN: [ CHUCKLES ]
[ SIGHS ]
GOD, SHE'S BEAUTIFUL.
AND FAST.
WARP 4.5 NEXT THURSDAY.
NEPTUNE AND BACK IN SIX MINUTES.
MAN: WHOO.
MAN: [ CHUCKLES ]
MAN: LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT THE LATERAL SENSOR ARRAY.
MAN: GIVE ME A SEC.
SLOW DOWN.
THERE.
THOSE ARE THE PORTS THAT BUCKLED
DURING THE LAST TEST.
THEY NEED TO BE REINFORCED.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
GREAT.
YOU SCRATCHED THE PAINT.
SORRY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ORBITAL SIX.
Man: Captain Archer, sir.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
Admiral Forrest needs you
at Starfleet Medical right away.
MAN: WHO WAS CHASING HIM?
VULCAN: WE DON'T KNOW.
THEY WERE INCINERATED
IN THE METHANE EXPLOSION,
AND THE FARMER'S DESCRIPTION
WAS VAGUE AT BEST.
HOW DID THEY GET HERE?
WHAT KIND OF SHIP?
VULCAN: THEY WERE USING SOME
KIND OF STEALTH TECHNOLOGY.
WE'RE STILL ANALYZING
OUR SENSOR LOGS.
I'D LIKE TO SEE THOSE LOGS.
VULCAN: THE KLINGONS
MADE IT VERY CLEAR
THEY WANT US TO EXPEDITE THIS.
IT HAPPENED ON OUR SOIL.
THAT'S IRRELEVANT.
AMBASSADOR,
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
WE HAVE A RIGHT TO KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
YOU WILL BE APPRISED OF
ALL PERTINENT INFORMATION.
AND JUST WHO GETS TO DECIDE
WHAT'S PERTINENT INFORMATION?
ADMIRAL.
JON.
I THINK YOU KNOW EVERYONE.
NOT EVERYONE.
MAN: IT'S A KLINGOT.
A KLINGON.
WHERE'D HE COME FROM?
MAN: OKLAHOMA.
A CORN FARMER NAMED MOORE
SHOT HIM WITH A PLASMA RIFLE.
SAYS IT WAS SELF-DEFENSE.
VULCAN: FORTUNATELY,
SOVAL AND I
HAVE MAINTAINED
CLOSE CONTACT WITH KRONOS
SINCE THE INCIDENT OCCURRED.
KRONOS?
IT'S THE KLINGONS' HOMEWORLD.
THIS GENTLEMAN'S
SOME SORT OF A COURIER.
EVIDENTLY, HE WAS CARRYING
CRUCIAL INFORMATION
BACK TO HIS PEOPLE.
WHEN HE WAS NEARLY KILLED
BY YOUR FARMER.
AMBASSADOR SOVAL
THINKS IT WOULD BE BEST
IF WE PUSH OFF YOUR LAUNCH
UNTIL WE'VE CLEARED THIS UP.
WELL, ISN'T THAT A SURPRISE?
YOU'D THINK THEY WOULD HAVE
COME UP WITH SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE IMAGINATIVE
THIS TIME.
SARCASM ASIDE, CAPTAIN,
THE LAST THING YOUR PEOPLE NEED
IS TO MAKE AN ENEMY
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
IF WE HADN'T CONVINCED THEM
TO LET US TAKE KLAANG'S CORPSE
BACK TO KRONOS,
EARTH WOULD MOST LIKELY
BE FACING A SQUADRON OF WARBIRDS
BY THE END OF THE WEEK.
CORPSE?
IS HE DEAD?
EXCUSE ME.
IS THIS MAN DEAD?
HIS AUTONOMIC SYSTEM
WAS DISRUPTED BY THE BLAST,
BUT HIS REDUNDANT
NEURAL FUNCTION --
IS HE GOING TO DIE?
NOT NECESSARILY.
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA DISCONNECT
THIS MAN FROM LIFE SUPPORT
EVEN THOUGH HE COULD LIVE.
NOW, WHERE'S THE LOGIC IN THAT?
KLAANG'S CULTURE FINDS
HONOR IN DEATH.
IF THEY SAW HIM LIKE THIS,
HE'D BE DISGRACED.
VULCAN: THEY'RE A WARRIOR RACE.
THEY DREAM OF DYING IN BATTLE.
IF YOU UNDERSTOOD
THE COMPLEXITIES
OF INTERSTELLAR DIPLOMACY --
SO THAT'S
YOUR DIPLOMATIC SOLUTION?
TO DO WHAT THEY TELL YOU?
PULL THE PLUG?
YOUR METAPHOR IS CRUDE...
BUT ACCURATE.
WE MAY BE CRUDE,
BUT WE'RE NOT MURDERERS.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA LET THEM
DO THIS, ARE YOU?
VULCAN: THE KLINGONS
HAVE DEMANDED
THAT WE RETURN
KLAANG IMMEDIATELY.
ADMIRAL?
WE MAY NEED TO DEFER
TO THEIR JUDGMENT.
WE'VE BEEN DEFERRING TO THEIR
JUDGMENT FOR A HUNDRED YEARS.
ADMIRAL: JON.
ARCHER: HOW MUCH LONGER?
WOMAN: UNTIL YOU'VE PROVEN
YOU'RE READY.
READY TO WHAT?
TO LOOK BEYOND YOUR
PROVINCIAL ATTITUDES
AND YOUR VOLATILE NATURE.
VOLATILE?
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
HOW MUCH I'M RESTRAINING MYSELF
FROM KNOCKING YOU ON YOUR ASS.
THESE KLINGONS, THEY'RE ANXIOUS
TO GET THEIR MAN BACK.
FINE. I CAN HAVE MY SHIP
READY TO GO IN THREE DAYS.
WE'LL TAKE HIM BACK HOME...
ALIVE.
VULCAN: THIS IS NO TIME TO BE
IMPOSING YOUR ETHICAL BELIEFS.
DAN?
WHAT ABOUT YOUR CREW?
YOUR COM OFFICER'S IN BRAZIL.
YOU HAVEN'T SELECTED
A MEDICAL OFFICER YET.
THREE DAYS -- THAT'S ALL I NEED.
ADMIRAL?
WE'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR NEARLY A CENTURY,
AMBASSADOR.
THIS SEEMS AS GOOD A TIME AS ANY
TO GET STARTED.
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'RE MAKING A MISTAKE!
ARCHER: WHEN YOUR LOGIC DOESN'T
WORK, YOU RAISE YOUR VOICE?
YOU'VE BEEN ON EARTH TOO LONG.
I HAD A FEELING THEIR APPROACH
WOULDN'T SIT TOO WELL WITH YOU.
DON'T SCREW THIS UP.
MAN: I HEARD THIS PLATFORM'S
BEEN APPROVED
FOR BIO-TRANSPORT.
MAN: I PRESUME YOU MEAN
FRUITS AND VEGETABLES.
I MEAN ARMORY OFFICERS
AND HELMSMEN.
I DON'T THINK I'M QUITE READY
TO HAVE MY MOLECULES COMPRESSED
INTO A DATA STREAM.
THEY CLAIM IT'S SAFE.
MAN: DO THEY, INDEED?
WELL, I CERTAINLY HOPE
THE CAPTAIN DOESN'T PLAN
ON MAKING US USE IT.
DON'T WORRY.
FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
HE WOULDN'T EVEN PUT HIS
DOG THROUGH THIS THING.
[ SIGHS ]
OHH.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I ASK FOR PLASMA COILS,
AND THEY SEND ME
A CASE OF VALVE SEALANT.
THERE'S NO CHANCE
I CAN HAVE THESE WEAPONS ONLINE
IN THREE DAYS.
WE'RE JUST TAKING A SICK MAN
BACK TO HIS HOMEWORLD.
WHY DO WE NEED WEAPONS?
DIDN'T YOU READ THE PROFILE
REPORT ON THESE KLINGONS?
MNH-MNH.
APPARENTLY,
THEY SHARPEN THEIR TEETH
BEFORE THEY GO INTO BATTLE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
NO DOUBT MR. TUCKER
WILL REASSURE ME
THAT MY EQUIPMENT
WILL BE HERE TOMORROW.
[ Imitating Tucker ] "KEEP
YOUR SHIRT ON, LIEUTENANT."
IS IT ME, OR DOES THE ARTIFICIAL
GRAVITY SEEM A BIT HEAVY?
[ Normal voice ]
FEELS ALL RIGHT.
EARTH SEA LEVEL.
MY FATHER ALWAYS
KEPT IT AT .8 "G" --
THOUGHT IT PUT
A LITTLE SPRING IN HIS STEP.
AFTER BEING RAISED
ON CARGO SHIPS,
IT MUST HAVE FELT LIKE YOU
HAD LEAD IN YOUR BOOTS
WHEN YOU GOT TO EARTH.
[PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: BEAUTIFUL.
LOCK IT OFF RIGHT THERE.
MAN: I BELIEVE
YOU MISSED A SPOT.
COMMANDER TUCKER,
ENSIGN TRAVIS MAYWEATHER.
HE JUST ARRIVED.
OUR SPACE BOOMER.
HOW FAST HAVE YOU GOTTEN HER?
WARP 4.
WE'LL BE GOING TO 4.5
AS SOON AS WE CLEAR JUPITER.
THINK YOU CAN HANDLE IT?
4.5?
MAN: PARDON ME,
BUT IF I DON'T REALIGN
THE DEFLECTOR,
THE FIRST GRAIN OF SPACE DUST
WE COME ACROSS
WILL BLOW A HOLE THROUGH
THIS SHIP THE SIZE OF YOUR FIST.
KEEP YOUR SHIRT ON, LIEUTENANT.
YOUR EQUIPMENT WILL BE HERE
IN THE MORNING.
[ WOMAN SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ PEOPLE REPEATING
IN KLINGON]
VERY GOOD.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ REPEATING IN KLINGON ]
CARLOS.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ CARLOS REPEATING IN KLINGON ]
[ REPEATING IN KLINGON ]
WOMAN: TIGHTEN THE BACK
OF YOUR TONGUE.
[ WOMAN SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ CARLOS REPEATING IN KLINGON ]
KEEP TRYING.
YOU'VE ALMOST GOT IT.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
IT'S TWO MORE WEEKS
BEFORE EXAMS.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
FOR ME TO LEAVE NOW.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE SOMEONE
WHO CAN COVER FOR YOU.
IF THERE WAS ANYONE ELSE
WHO CAN DO WHAT I DO,
YOU WOULDN'T BE SO EAGER
TO HAVE ME ON YOUR SPACESHIP.
HOSHI.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I OWE IT TO THESE KIDS.
I COULD ORDER YOU.
I'M ON LEAVE FROM STARFLEET,
REMEMBER?
YOU WOULD HAVE TO
FORCIBLY RECALL ME,
WHICH WOULD
REQUIRE A REPRIMAND,
WHICH WOULD DISQUALIFY ME
FROM SERVING ON
AN ACTIVE VESSEL.
I NEED SOMEONE
WITH YOUR EAR.
AND YOU'LL HAVE HER
IN THREE WEEKS.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
W-WHAT'S THAT?
KLINGON.
AMBASSADOR SOVAL
GAVE US A SAMPLING
OF THEIR LINGUISTIC DATABASE.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID THE VULCANS
WERE OPPOSED TO THIS.
THEY ARE.
BUT WE AGREED TO MAKE
A FEW COMPROMISES.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THESE KLINGONS?
NOT MUCH.
AN EMPIRE OF WARRIORS...
WITH 80 POLYGUTTURAL DIALECTS
CONSTRUCTED
ON AN ADAPTIVE SYNTAX.
TURN IT UP.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
ARCHER: THINK OF IT.
YOU'D BE THE FIRST HUMAN
TO TALK TO THESE PEOPLE.
DO YOU REALLY WANT
SOMEONE ELSE TO DO IT?
SINCE WHEN DO WE HAVE
VULCAN SCIENCE OFFICERS?
SINCE WE NEEDED
THEIR STARCHARTS
TO GET TO KRONOS.
SO WE GET A FEW MAPS, AND THEY
GET TO PUT A SPY ON OUR SHIP?
ADMIRAL FORREST SAYS
WE SHOULD THINK OF HER
MORE AS A CHAPERONE.
I THOUGHT
THE WHOLE POINT OF THIS
WAS TO GET AWAY
FROM THE VULCANS.
FOUR DAYS THERE
AND FOUR DAYS BACK.
THEN SHE'S GONE.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE'RE TO EXTEND HER
EVERY COURTESY.
I DON'T KNOW.
I'D BE MORE COMFORTABLE
WITH PORTHOS ON THE BRIDGE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
HERE WE GO.
COME IN.
THIS CONFIRMS THAT I WAS
TRANSFERRED TO YOUR COMMAND
AT 0800 HOURS.
REPORTING FOR DUTY.
[ SNIFFING ]
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
NO, SIR.
OH, I FORGOT.
VULCAN FEMALES HAVE
A HEIGHTENED SENSE OF SMELL.
I HOPE PORTHOS ISN'T
TOO OFFENSIVE TO YOU.
VULCAN: I'VE BEEN TRAINED TO
TOLERATE OFFENSIVE SITUATIONS.
I TOOK A SHOWER THIS MORNING.
HOW ABOUT YOU, CAPTAIN?
I'M SORRY. THIS IS
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER III.
SUBCOMMANDER T'POL.
TRIP. I'M CALLED TRIP.
I'LL TRY TO REMEMBER THAT.
WHILE YOU MAY NOT SHARE OUR
ENTHUSIASM ABOUT THIS MISSION,
I EXPECT YOU TO FOLLOW
OUR RULES.
WHAT'S SAID IN THIS ROOM
AND OUT ON THAT BRIDGE
IS PRIVILEGED INFORMATION.
I DON'T WANT EVERY WORD I SAY
BEING PICKED APART THE NEXT DAY
BY THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND.
MY REASON FOR BEING HERE
IS NOT ESPIONAGE.
MY SUPERIORS SIMPLY ASKED ME
TO ASSIST YOU.
YOUR SUPERIORS DON'T THINK
WE CAN FLUSH A TOILET
WITHOUT ONE OF YOU TO ASSIST US.
I DIDN'T REQUEST
THIS ASSIGNMENT, CAPTAIN,
AND YOU CAN BE CERTAIN
THAT WHEN THIS MISSION'S OVER,
I'LL BE AS PLEASED TO LEAVE THIS
SHIP AS YOU'LL BE TO HAVE ME GO.
[ WHIMPERING ]
IF THERE'S NOTHING ELSE.
THAT'LL BE ALL.
WHEN ZEFRAM COCHRANE
MADE HIS LEGENDARY WARP FLIGHT
90 YEARS AGO
AND DREW THE ATTENTION OF
OUR NEW FRIENDS, THE VULCANS,
WE REALIZED THAT WE WEREN'T
ALONE IN THE GALAXY.
TODAY, WE ARE ABOUT TO CROSS
A NEW THRESHOLD.
FOR NEARLY A CENTURY,
WE'VE WADED ANKLE-DEEP
IN THE OCEAN OF SPACE.
NOW IT'S FINALLY TIME TO SWIM.
[ APPLAUSE,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
THE WARP 5 ENGINE
WOULDN'T BE A REALITY
WITHOUT MEN LIKE
DR. COCHRANE AND HENRY ARCHER,
WHO WORKED SO HARD
TO DEVELOP IT.
SO IT'S ONLY FITTING THAT
HENRY'S SON, JONATHAN ARCHER,
WILL COMMAND THE FIRST STARSHIP
POWERED BY THAT ENGINE.
[ APPLAUSE,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
RATHER THAN QUOTING
DR. COCHRANE,
I THINK WE SHOULD LISTEN
TO HIS OWN WORDS
FROM THE DEDICATION CEREMONY
FOR THE WARP 5 COMPLEX
32 YEARS AGO.
COCHRANE: ON THIS SITE,
A POWERFUL ENGINE
WILL BE BUILT,
AN ENGINE THAT WILL SOMEDAY
HELP US
TO TRAVEL A HUNDRED TIMES
FASTER THAN WE CAN TODAY.
IMAGINE IT -- THOUSANDS
OF INHABITED PLANETS
AT OUR FINGERTIPS,
AND WE'LL BE ABLE TO EXPLORE
THOSE STRANGE NEW WORLDS
AND SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS.
THIS ENGINE
WILL LET US GO BOLDLY
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
TAKE HER OUT, MR. MAYWEATHER.
STRAIGHT AND STEADY.
Archer: How we doing, Trip?
READY WHEN YOU ARE.
PREPARE FOR WARP.
COURSE LAID IN, SIR.
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO GET UNDERWAY.
THE COORDINATES ARE OFF
BY .2 DEGREES.
THANK YOU.
LET'S GO.
ALIEN: WHERE'S KLAANG?
THE HUMANS HAVE HIM.
DID YOU LOSE ANYONE ELSE?
TWO OF MY SOLDIERS WERE KILLED.
ONE OF THEM WAS A FRIEND.
CAN YOU PREVENT IT?
OUR AGREEMENT DOESN'T PROVIDE
FOR CORRECTING MISTAKES.
RECOVER THE EVIDENCE.
I WILL, I PROMISE YOU.
WHEN WILL WE SPEAK AGAIN?
DON'T BE CONCERNED WITH WHEN.
LOVE WHAT YOU'VE DONE
WITH THE PLACE.
DOCTOR: THOSE ARE
IMMUNOCYTIC GEL WORMS.
TRY NOT TO SHAKE THEM.
ARCHER: WHAT'D YOU
THINK OF EARTH?
DOCTOR: INTRIGUING. I ESPECIALLY
LIKED THE CHINESE FOOD.
HAVE YOU EVER TRIED IT?
ARCHER: I LIVED IN
SAN FRANCISCO ALL MY LIFE.
DOCTOR: AH.
ANATOMICALLY, YOU HUMANS
ARE SOMEWHAT SIMPLISTIC,
BUT WHAT YOU LACK BIOLOGICALLY,
YOU MAKE UP FOR WITH
YOUR CHARMING OPTIMISM.
NOT TO MENTION
YOUR EGG DROP SOUP.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BE VERY CAREFUL WITH THAT.
[ ANIMAL CHITTERING ]
WHAT'S IN THERE?
AN ALTARIAN MARSUPIAL.
[ IMITATES CHITTERING ]
THEIR DROPPINGS CONTAIN
THE GREATEST CONCENTRATION
OF REGENERATIVE ENZYMES
FOUND ANYWHERE.
THEIR DROPPINGS?
IF YOU'RE GOING TO TRY
TO EMBRACE NEW WORLDS,
YOU MUST TRY
TO EMBRACE NEW IDEAS.
THAT'S WHY THE VULCANS INITIATED
THE INTERSPECIES
MEDICAL EXCHANGE.
THERE'S A LOT TO BE LEARNED.
I'M SORRY TO TAKE YOU AWAY
FROM YOUR PROGRAM,
BUT OUR DOCTORS HAVEN'T
EVEN HEARD OF A KLINGON.
DOCTOR:
PLEASE, NO APOLOGIES.
WHAT BETTER TIME
TO STUDY HUMAN BEINGS
THAN WHEN THEY'RE
UNDER PRESSURE?
IT'S A RARE OPPORTUNITY,
AND YOUR KLINGON FRIEND -- AH.
I'VE NEVER HAD THE CHANCE TO
EXAMINE A LIVING ONE BEFORE.
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER TELLS ME
THAT WE'LL BE TO KRONOS
IN ABOUT 80 HOURS.
ANY CHANCE HE'LL BE CONSCIOUS
BY THEN?
THERE'S A CHANCE
HE'LL BE CONSCIOUS
WITHIN THE NEXT 10 MINUTES --
JUST NOT A VERY GOOD ONE.
80 HOURS, DOCTOR.
IF HE DOESN'T WALK OFF THIS SHIP
ON HIS OWN TWO FEET,
HE DOESN'T
STAND MUCH OF A CHANCE.
DOCTOR: I'LL DO
THE BEST I CAN.
OPTIMISM, CAPTAIN!
YOU'RE UPSIDE DOWN, ENSIGN.
ENSIGN: YES, SIR.
CARE TO EXPLAIN WHY?
WHEN I WAS A KID,
WE CALLED IT THE SWEET SPOT.
EVERY SHIP'S GOT ONE.
SWEET SPOT?
IT'S USUALLY ABOUT HALFWAY
BETWEEN THE GRAV GENERATOR
AND THE BOW PLATE.
GRAB AHOLD OF THE HATCH.
NO, NO, NO, ON EITHER SIDE.
NOW PUSH OFF.
PUSH OFF.
WOW.
WHOA!
UGH!
ENSIGN: TAKES PRACTICE.
YOU EVER SLEPT IN ZERO "G"?
SLEPT?
IT'S JUST LIKE BEING
BACK IN THE WOMB.
THE CAPTAIN TELLS ME
YOU'VE BEEN TO TRILLIUS PRIME.
IT TOOK FOURTH, FIFTH,
AND SIXTH GRADES TO GET THERE.
I'VE ALSO BEEN TO DRAYLAX
AND BOTH THE TENEEBIAN MOONS.
I'VE ONLY BEEN ON ONE
INHABITED PLANET BESIDES EARTH.
NOTHING THERE
BUT DUST-DWELLING TICKS.
I'VE HEARD THE WOMEN
ON DRAYLAX HAVE --
THREE.
YEAH, IT'S TRUE.
YOU KNOW THAT FIRSTHAND?
FIRSTHAND,
SECONDHAND, THIRDHAND.
I GUESS GROWING UP A BOOMER
HAS ITS ADVANTAGES.
[ CHUCKLING ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
GOT AN EMPTY SEAT
HERE, COMMANDER.
SORRY, DINNER
WITH THE BOSS TONIGHT.
ARCHER: GRAND CANYON?
T'POL: NO.
BIG SUR AQUARIUM.
SIGHTSEEING WAS NOT
ONE OF MY ASSIGNMENTS.
HMM.
ALL WORK AND NO PLAY.
EVERYBODY SHOULD GET OUT
FOR A LITTLE FUN NOW AND THEN.
ALL OUR RECREATIONAL NEEDS
ARE PROVIDED AT THE COMPOUND.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
YOU SHOULD HAVE STARTED
WITHOUT ME.
ARCHER: SIT DOWN.
T'POL TELLS ME
SHE'S BEEN LIVING
AT THE VULCAN COMPOUND
IN SAUSALITO.
TRIP: NO KIDDING.
I LIVED A FEW BLOCKS FROM THERE
WHEN I FIRST JOINED STARFLEET.
GREAT PARTIES
AT THE VULCAN COMPOUND.
[ CHUCKLES ]
IT MIGHT BE A LITTLE EASIER
USING YOUR FINGERS.
VULCANS DON'T TOUCH FOOD
WITH THEIR HANDS.
TRIP: CAN'T WAIT TO SEE YOU
TACKLE THE SPARE RIBS.
DON'T WORRY.
WE KNOW YOU'RE A VEGETARIAN.
LOOKS DELICIOUS.
TELL CHEF I SAID THANKS.
OF COURSE, SIR.
YOU HUMANS CLAIM
TO BE ENLIGHTENED,
YET YOU STILL CONSUME
THE FLESH OF ANIMALS.
GRANDMA TAUGHT ME NEVER JUDGE A
SPECIES BY THEIR EATING HABITS.
ARCHER: ENLIGHTENED
MIGHT BE TOO STRONG A WORD,
BUT IF YOU'D BEEN ON EARTH
50 YEARS AGO,
I THINK YOU'D BE IMPRESSED
BY WHAT WE'VE GOTTEN DONE.
YOU HAVE YET TO EMBRACE
EITHER PATIENCE OR LOGIC.
YOU REMAIN IMPULSIVE CARNIVORES.
YEAH?
HOW ABOUT WAR, DISEASE, HUNGER?
PRETTY MUCH WIPED THEM OUT
IN LESS THAN TWO GENERATIONS.
I WOULDN'T CALL THAT
SMALL POTATOES.
IT REMAINS TO BE SEEN
WHETHER HUMANITY WILL REVERT
TO ITS BASER INSTINCTS.
WELL, WE USED TO HAVE CANNIBALS
ON EARTH.
WHO KNOWS HOW FAR WE'LL REVERT?
LUCKY THIS ISN'T A LONG MISSION.
HUMAN INSTINCT IS PRETTY STRONG.
YOU CAN'T EXPECT US
TO CHANGE OVERNIGHT.
WITH PROPER DISCIPLINE...
ANYTHING'S POSSIBLE.
ENSIGN: WARP 4.3, SIR.
NOT MUCH OF A CHANGE.
I DON'T KNOW.
DOES ANYBODY ELSE FEEL THAT?
FEEL WHAT?
HOSHI: THOSE VIBRATIONS,
LIKE LITTLE TREMORS?
YOU'RE IMAGINING IT.
BRING US TO 4.4, ENSIGN.
[ RUMBLING ]
THERE. WHAT DO YOU CALL THAT?
THE DEFLECTOR'S SEQUENCING.
IT'S PERFECTLY NORMAL.
PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE TO GO
TO YOUR QUARTERS AND LIE DOWN.
[ SPEAKING VULCAN ]
I WAS INSTRUCTED TO SPEAK
ENGLISH ON THIS VOYAGE,
AND I'D APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU'D RESPECT THAT.
IT'S EASY TO GET A LITTLE JUMPY
WHEN YOU'RE TRAVELING AT
30 MILLION KILOMETERS A SECOND.
SHOULD BE OLD HAT
IN A WEEK'S TIME.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
Doctor: This is
Dr. Phlox, Captain.
Our patient
is regaining consciousness.
ON MY WAY.
HOSHI.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
ARCHER: WHAT'S WRONG?
THE TRANSLATOR.
IT'S NOT -- NOT LOCKING ON
TO HIS DIALECT.
THE -- THE SYNTAX WON'T ALIGN.
UH...
TELL HIM WE'RE TAKING HIM HOME.
UM...
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
OH, HE -- HE WANTS
TO KNOW WHO WE ARE.
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
SHIP -- HE'S ASKING
FOR HIS SHIP BACK.
SAY IT WAS DESTROYED.
[ BOTH SPEAKING KLINGON ]
I-I'M NOT SURE,
BUT I THINK HE SAID
SOMETHING ABOUT
EATING THE AFTERLIFE?
TRY THE TRANSLATOR AGAIN.
I-I-I'M GONNA NEED
TO RUN WHAT WE'VE GOT
THROUGH THE PHONETIC PROCESSOR.
HE SAYS -- HE SAYS...
HIS WIFE HAS GROWN UGLY?
I AM SORRY, CAPTAIN!
I'M DOING THE BEST I CAN.
EXCUSE ME.
HIS PREFRONTAL CORTEX
IS HYPERSTIMULATED.
I DOUBT HE HAS
ANY IDEA WHAT HE'S SAYING.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
I THINK THE DOCTOR'S RIGHT,
CAPTAIN,
UNLESS STINKY BOOTS HAS
SOMETHING TO DO WITH ALL THIS.
[ RUMBLING ]
T-T-THAT'S THE WARP REACTOR
AGAIN, RIGHT?
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
BRIDGE, REPORT.
T'Pol: We've dropped
out of warp, sir.
Main power -- [ Static ]
ENSIGN: WE'RE LOSING
POWER ON ALL DECKS.
I THINK I JUST SAW SOMETHING
OFF THE STARBOARD BOW.
T'POL: WHAT?
LIEUTENANT: I DON'T KNOW.
IT MIGHT HAVE JUST BEEN
THE SENSORS GOING DOWN.
[ SHOUTING IN KLINGON ]
ARCHER: AUXILIARY POWER SHOULD
HAVE KICKED IN BY NOW.
YOU WANT TO TELL HIM TO SHUT UP?
SHUT UP!
ARCHER: YOU MAY
HAVE TO SEDATE HIM.
I NEED TO GET TO THE BRIDGE.
HOSHI: CAPTAIN!
THERE'S SOMEONE HERE.
[ CLATTERING ]
ARCHER: CREWMAN!
SULIBAN.
[ GRUNTING ]
HOSHI: AAH!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
CREWMAN: YEAH.
WE'VE GOT
STATE-OF-THE-ART SENSORS.
WHY THE HELL DIDN'T
WE DETECT THEM?
MR. REED THOUGHT
HE DETECTED SOMETHING
RIGHT BEFORE WE LOST POWER.
REED: THE STARBOARD SENSOR LOGS
RECORDED A SPATIAL DISTURBANCE.
LOOKS MORE LIKE A GLITCH.
THOSE WEREN'T GLITCHES
IN SICK BAY.
I WANT A COMPLETE ANALYSIS
OF THAT DISTURBANCE.
WHERE DO WE STAND ON WEAPONS?
I STILL HAVE TO TUNE
THE TARGETING SCANNERS.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: THE KLINGONS SEEMED
TO KNOW WHO THEY WERE.
SEE IF YOU CAN TRANSLATE
WHAT HE SAID.
HOSHI: RIGHT AWAY.
T'POL: CAPTAIN, THERE'S NO WAY
YOU COULD HAVE
ANTICIPATED THIS.
I'M SURE AMBASSADOR SOVAL
WILL UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE THE SCIENCE OFFICER.
WHY DON'T YOU HELP TRIP
WITH THAT ANALYSIS?
T'POL: THE ASTROMETRIC
COMPUTER IN SAN FRANCISCO
WILL BE FAR MORE EFFECTIVE.
WE'RE NOT GOING
TO SAN FRANCISCO,
SO MAKE DO WITH
WHAT WE'VE GOT HERE.
T'POL: YOU'VE LOST THE KLINGON.
YOUR MISSION IS OVER.
I DIDN'T LOSE THE KLINGON.
HE WAS TAKEN.
AND I'M GOING
TO FIND OUT WHO TOOK HIM.
HOW DO YOU PLAN TO DO THAT?
SPACE IS VERY BIG, CAPTAIN.
A SHADOW ON YOUR SENSORS
WON'T HELP YOU FIND THEM.
THIS IS A FOOLISH MISSION.
COME WITH ME.
I'M NOT INTERESTED IN WHAT
YOU THINK ABOUT THIS MISSION,
SO TAKE YOUR VULCAN CYNICISM
AND BURY IT
ALONG WITH
YOUR REPRESSED EMOTIONS.
YOUR REACTION TO THIS SITUATION
IS A PERFECT EXAMPLE
OF WHY YOUR SPECIES SHOULD
REMAIN IN ITS OWN STAR SYSTEM.
I'VE BEEN LISTENING
TO YOU VULCANS
TELL US WHAT NOT TO DO
MY ENTIRE LIFE.
I WATCHED MY FATHER
WORK HIS ASS OFF
WHILE YOUR SCIENTISTS HELD BACK
JUST ENOUGH INFORMATION
TO KEEP HIM FROM SUCCEEDING.
HE DESERVED TO SEE THAT LAUNCH.
YOU MAY HAVE LIFE-SPANS
OF 200 YEARS. WE DON'T.
T'POL: YOU ARE GOING TO BE
CONTACTING STARFLEET
TO ADVISE THEM OF OUR SITUATION.
NO, I'M NOT,
AND NEITHER ARE YOU.
NOW GET THE HELL OUT THERE
AND MAKE YOURSELF USEFUL.
ARCHER: WHAT HAVE
YOU FOUND, DOCTOR?
DOCTOR: MR. KLAANG
WAS RIGHT ABOUT ONE THING.
HE IS A SULIBAN.
BUT UNLESS I'M MISTAKEN,
HE IS NO ORDINARY ONE.
ARCHER: MEANING?
HIS DNA IS SULIBAN, BUT HIS
ANATOMY HAS BEEN ALTERED.
LOOK AT THIS LUNG.
DOCTOR: FIVE BRONCHIAL
LOBES, YOU SEE.
IT SHOULD ONLY HAVE THREE. HMM.
AND LOOK
AT THE ALVEOLI CLUSTERS.
THEY'VE BEEN MODIFIED
TO PROCESS DIFFERENT KINDS
OF ATMOSPHERE.
ARE YOU SAYING HE'S
SOME KIND OF A MUTANT?
WELL, I, UH -- I SUPPOSE I AM,
BUT THIS WAS NO ACCIDENT --
NO, UH, FREAK OF NATURE.
THIS MAN WAS THE RECIPIENT
OF SOME VERY SOPHISTICATED
GENETIC ENGINEERING.
WATCH THIS.
SUBCUTANEOUS PIGMENT SACS.
MM.
A BIOMIMETIC GARMENT.
AND THE EYES ARE MY FAVORITE.
COMPOUND RETINAS.
HE MOST LIKELY SAW THINGS EVEN
YOUR SENSORS COULDN'T DETECT.
ARCHER: IT'S NOT
IN THEIR GENOME?
DOCTOR: NO, CERTAINLY NOT.
THE SULIBAN ARE NO MORE
EVOLVED THAN HUMANS.
IT IS VERY IMPRESSIVE WORK,
THOUGH.
NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
QUITE LIKE IT.
TRIP: HOW ABOUT THIS?
T'POL: IT'S JUST
BACKGROUND NOISE.
YOUR SENSORS AREN'T CAPABLE
OF ISOLATING PLASMA DECAY.
HOW CAN YOU BE SO DAMN SURE
WHAT OUR SENSORS CAN DO?
VULCAN CHILDREN PLAY WITH TOYS
THAT ARE MORE SOPHISTICATED.
YOU KNOW,
SOME PEOPLE SAY YOU VULCANS
DO NOTHING BUT PATRONIZE US,
BUT IF THEY WERE HERE NOW,
IF THEY COULD SEE HOW FAR
YOU'RE BENDING OVER BACKWARDS
TO HELP ME,
THEY'D EAT THEIR WORDS.
YOUR CAPTAIN'S MISSION
WAS TO RETURN THE KLINGON
TO HIS PEOPLE.
HE NO LONGER HAS THE KLINGON.
I REALIZE HE'S ONLY
A SIMPLE EARTHLING,
BUT DID IT EVER OCCUR
TO YOU THAT HE MIGHT
KNOW WHAT HE'S DOING?
IT'S NO SECRET STARFLEET
HASN'T BEEN AROUND TOO LONG.
GOD KNOWS YOU REMIND US OF THAT
EVERY CHANCE YOU GET.
DOES THAT MEAN THE MAN
WHO'S BEEN PUT IN CHARGE
OF THIS MISSION
DOESN'T DESERVE OUR SUPPORT?
THEN AGAIN,
LOYALTY'S AN EMOTION.
ISN'T IT?
ARCHER: ANY LUCK?
TRIP: NOT REALLY.
MY ANALYSIS OF THE
SPATIAL DISTURBANCE MR. REED SAW
INDICATES A STEALTH VESSEL
WITH A TRICYCLIC PLASMA DRIVE.
REED: IF WE CAN FIGURE OUT THE
DECAY RATE OF THEIR PLASMA,
WE'LL BE ABLE TO FIND
THE WARP TRAIL.
T'POL: UNFORTUNATELY,
YOUR SENSORS
WERE NOT DESIGNED
TO MEASURE PLASMA DECAY.
ARE YOU SURE IT'S SAFE
TO STAND SO CLOSE TO THAT?
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
I'VE MANAGED TO TRANSLATE
MOST OF WHAT KLAANG SAID,
BUT NONE OF IT MAKES SENSE.
ARCHER: NOTHING ABOUT
THE SULIBAN?
NOPE.
DOES THAT NAME RING A BELL
TO YOU?
THEY'RE A SOMEWHAT PRIMITIVE
SPECIES FROM SECTOR 3641,
BUT THEY'VE NEVER
POSED A THREAT.
WELL, THEY HAVE NOW.
DID HE SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT EARTH?
THE WORD'S NOT EVEN IN THEIR
DATABASE. IT'S ALL THERE.
THERE ARE ONLY FOUR WORDS
THAT I COULDN'T TRANSLATE,
PROBABLY JUST PROPER NOUNS.
JELIK, SARIN,
RIGEL, THOLIA.
ANYTHING SOUND FAMILIAR?
T'POL?
RIGEL IS A PLANETARY SYSTEM
APPROXIMATELY 15 LIGHT-YEARS
FROM OUR PRESENT POSITION.
WHY THE HESITATION?
ACCORDING TO
THE NAVIGATIONAL LOG
SALVAGED FROM KLAANG'S SHIP,
RIGEL TEN WAS THE LAST PLACE
HE STOPPED
BEFORE CRASHING ON YOUR PLANET.
WHY DO I GET THE FEELING
YOU WEREN'T GONNA SHARE
THAT LITTLE PIECE
OF INFORMATION?
I WASN'T AUTHORIZED TO REVEAL
THE DETAILS OF OUR FINDINGS.
THE NEXT TIME I LEARN
YOU'RE WITHHOLDING SOMETHING,
YOU'RE GONNA SPEND
THE REST OF THIS VOYAGE
CONFINED TO SOME
VERY CRAMPED QUARTERS.
UNDERSTOOD?
ARCHER: ARCHER TO HELM.
Ensign: Mayweather.
GO INTO THE VULCAN STARCHARTS
AND FIND A SYSTEM CALLED RIGEL.
THEN SET A COURSE
FOR THE TENTH PLANET.
Ensign: Yes, sir.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
SULIBAN: ARE YOU CERTAIN
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH?
ABSOLUTELY CERTAIN.
THE DRUGS ARE WORKING.
KEEP HIM ALIVE
WHILE I'M GONE.
ARCHER: AS SOON AS
WE'VE TIED DOWN,
WE'LL BE DESCENDING
INTO THE TRADE COMPLEX.
IT HAS 36 LEVELS.
T'POL: YOUR TRANSLATORS HAVE
BEEN PROGRAMMED FOR RIGELIAN.
HOWEVER, YOU'LL ENCOUNTER
NUMEROUS OTHER SPECIES.
MANY OF THEM ARE KNOWN TO BE
IMPATIENT WITH NEWCOMERS.
NONE OF THEM HAVE SEEN
A HUMAN BEFORE.
YOU HAVE A TENDENCY
TO BE GREGARIOUS.
I SUGGEST YOU TRY
TO RESTRAIN THAT TENDENCY.
YOU FORGOT TO WARN US
ABOUT DRINKING THE WATER.
DR. PHLOX ISN'T CONCERNED
WITH THE FOOD AND WATER,
BUT HE DOES CAUTION
AGAINST INTIMATE CONTACT.
ARCHER: THE VULCANS TOLD US
KLAANG WAS A COURIER.
IF HE WAS THERE
TO GET SOMETHING,
WHOEVER GAVE IT TO HIM
MIGHT KNOW WHY HE WAS TAKEN.
IT WAS JUST A FEW DAYS AGO.
A SEVEN-FOOT KLINGON
DOESN'T GO UNNOTICED.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ HIGH-PITCHED SCREAMING ]
WHAT IN THE WORLD?
IT'S NOTHING THAT CONCERNS US.
[ SLOW MUSIC PLAYS ]
WOULD YOU LIKE TO MEET THEM?
I CAN ARRANGE IT.
IS THIS WHERE YOU SAW KLAANG?
I'LL SHOW YOU WHERE,
BUT FIRST,
YOU SHOULD ENJOY YOURSELVES.
WHICH ONE WOULD YOU PREFER?
WE SHOULD GET GOING.
ARE THOSE REAL BUTTERFLIES
OR SOME KIND OF HOLOGRAMS?
SIR.
OH, YES, ABSOLUTELY.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
[ CHATTERING ]
[ GASPING ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
T'POL TO ARCHER.
Archer: Go ahead.
HEY!
CENTRAL SECURITY CLAIMS TO HAVE
NO RECORD OF KLAANG,
BUT THEY TOLD ME ABOUT
AN ENCLAVE ON LEVEL 19
WHERE KLINGONS HAVE
BEEN KNOWN TO GO.
SOMETHING ABOUT LIVE FOOD.
Archer: Where on level 19?
THE EASTERNMOST SUBSECTION,
BY THE GEOTHERMAL SHAFTS.
Archer: I'll meet you there
as soon as I can.
Archer: Archer out.
TRIP: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TRIP: LEAVE THE KID ALONE!
T'POL: DON'T GET INVOLVED.
YOU SEE WHAT SHE'S DOING?
HE'S GONNA SUFFOCATE.
THEY'RE LORILLIANS.
BEFORE THE AGE OF 4, THEY CAN
ONLY BREATHE METHYL OXIDE.
THE MOTHER IS SIMPLY WEANING
HER SON.
COULD HAVE FOOLED ME.
HUMANS CAN'T REFRAIN
FROM DRAWING CONCLUSIONS.
YOU SHOULD LEARN
TO OBJECTIFY OTHER CULTURES,
SO YOU KNOW WHEN TO INTERFERE
AND WHEN NOT TO.
HOSHI: ISN'T AN ENCLAVE
SUPPOSED TO HAVE PEOPLE?
ARCHER: ENCLAVE CAN MEAN
A LOT OF THINGS.
HOSHI: T'POL SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT LIVE FOOD.
I DON'T SEE ANY RESTAURANTS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ARCHER: HELLO?
EXCUSE ME!
[ HOSHI SPEAKING KLINGON ]
THEY LOOKED KLINGON TO ME.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO T'POL.
[ Static ]
T'POL, COME IN.
[ CLATTERING ]
MAYBE WE SHOULD GET BACK
TO WHERE THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF PEOPLE
RIGHT HERE.
[ PHASE PISTOL CHARGES ]
STAY BEHIND ME.
AAH!
WOMAN: YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR KLAANG.
WHY?
ARCHER:
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS SARIN.
TELL ME ABOUT THE PEOPLE
WHO TOOK KLAANG OFF YOUR SHIP.
I WAS HOPING YOU COULD TELL ME.
THEY LOOKED A LOT LIKE
YOUR FRIENDS OUTSIDE.
WHERE WERE YOU TAKING HIM?
WHY DON'T YOU
LOOK LIKE YOUR FRIENDS?
WOULD YOU PREFER I DID?
WHAT I'D PREFER IS
YOU GIVE ME KLAANG BACK.
SO YOU COULD TAKE HIM WHERE?
HOME.
WE WERE JUST TAKING HIM HOME.
YOU BETTER BE CAREFUL.
I'M A LOT BIGGER THAN YOU ARE.
IF YOU'RE THINKING OF HARMING
ME, I'D ADVISE AGAINST IT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHY WERE YOU TAKING KLAANG HOME?
YOU KNOW, UNDER
DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES,
I MIGHT BE FLATTERED
BY THIS, BUT I --
THAT'S NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE.
I'VE BEEN GIVEN THE ABILITY
TO MEASURE TRUST,
BUT IT REQUIRES CLOSE CONTACT.
YOU'RE SULIBAN.
I WAS A MEMBER OF THE CABAL,
BUT NOT ANY LONGER.
THE PRICE OF EVOLUTION
WAS TOO HIGH.
EVOLUTION?
SOME OF MY PEOPLE
ARE SO ANXIOUS
TO IMPROVE THEMSELVES
THAT THEY'VE LOST PERSPECTIVE.
SO YOU KNOW I'M
NOT LYING TO YOU.
NOW WHAT?
KLAANG WAS CARRYING A MESSAGE
TO HIS PEOPLE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
I GAVE IT TO HIM.
WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE?
THE SULIBAN HAVE BEEN
STAGING ATTACKS
WITHIN THE KLINGON EMPIRE,
MAKING IT APPEAR THAT ONE
FACTION IS ATTACKING ANOTHER.
KLAANG WAS BRINGING PROOF
OF THIS TO HIS HIGH COUNCIL.
WITHOUT THAT PROOF,
THE EMPIRE COULD BE
THROWN INTO CHAOS.
WHY WOULD THE SULIBAN
WANT THAT?
SARIN: THE CABAL DOESN'T MAKE
DECISIONS ON ITS OWN.
THEY'RE SIMPLY SOLDIERS FIGHTING
A TEMPORAL COLD WAR.
TEMPORAL?
YOU'VE LOST ME.
THEY'RE TAKING ORDERS
FROM THE DISTANT FUTURE.
WHAT?
SARIN: WE CAN HELP YOU
FIND KLAANG,
BUT WE DON'T HAVE A STARSHIP.
YOU'LL HAVE TO TAKE US WITH YOU.
SARIN: WHERE'S YOUR VESSEL?
ARCHER: ON THE ROOF.
DOCKING PORT 3.
SARIN: THIS WAY.
SARIN: UHH! UHH!
TRIP.
FIND KLAANG.
WHERE'S THE POD?
OVER HERE.
NO, IT'S THIS WAY.
COME ON.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
LIEUTENANT REED, THIS IS ARCHER.
COME IN.
[ Static ]
WE'RE ON THE ROOF.
YOU NEED TO GET UP HERE
AS QUICKLY AS YOU CAN.
[ Static ]
WE'VE BEEN TRYING
TO REACH YOU, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE BACK IN THE SHUTTLE.
ENSIGN: ASK HIM
WHERE THEY ARE.
THE STORM'S GETTING WORSE.
REED: CAPTAIN,
WHAT'S YOUR LOCATION?
THE WEATHER IS DEFINITELY...
[ Static ]
HOSHI: GREAT!
ARCHER: LIKE I SAID,
IT'S BACK THERE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN LIGHTNING
IN A SNOWSTORM BEFORE.
THE STORM'S KICKING UP
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE.
I CAN'T ISOLATE HUMAN BIO-SIGNS.
THEY COULD BE ANYWHERE
IN THE COMPLEX.
TRY VULCAN BIO-SIGNS.
[ POUNDING ]
I FOUND HER.
[ GRUNTS ]
GET HOSHI TO THE SHIP.
NOW!
ARCHER: GO!
ENTERPRISE NEEDS ITS CAPTAIN.
GIVE ME THE WEAPONS.
I SAID GO!
[ GROANING ]
THE STARBOARD THRUSTER'S DOWN.
IGNORE IT. TAKE US UP.
[ GROANING ]
WE NEED INSTRUCTIONS.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
T'POL: SUBCOMMANDER T'POL
TO ENTERPRISE.
Man: Go ahead.
WE'LL BE DOCKING
IN FOUR MINUTES.
HAVE DR. PHLOX
MEET US IN DECON.
Man: Acknowledged.
Is someone wounded?
THE CAPTAIN.
I'M TAKING COMMAND
OF ENTERPRISE.
BOY: I CAN'T DO IT.
MAN: YES, YOU CAN.
TAKE HER UP,
STRAIGHT AND STEADY.
BOY: DAMN.
YOU CAN'T BE
AFRAID OF THE WIND.
LEARN TO TRUST IT.
IT SHOULDN'T TAKE
MORE THAN A FEW MOMENTS.
IS THIS REALLY NECESSARY?
THE OTHERS SCANNED NEGATIVE.
YOU TWO, UNFORTUNATELY,
WERE EXPOSED
TO A PROTOCYSTIAN SPORE.
I'VE LOADED THE APPROPRIATE
DECON GEL INTO COMPARTMENT "B."
TELL MR. MAYWEATHER
TO PREPARE TO LEAVE ORBIT.
TRIP: HOW'S THE CAPTAIN?
DOCTOR:
I'M TREATING HIS WOUND.
TRIP: WILL HE BE ALL RIGHT?
DOCTOR: EVENTUALLY.
CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG,
BUT AREN'T YOU JUST KIND
OF AN OBSERVER ON THIS MISSION?
I DON'T REMEMBER
ANYONE TELLING ME
YOU WERE A MEMBER
OF STARFLEET.
MY VULCAN RANK
SUPERSEDES YOURS.
APPLES AND ORANGES.
THIS IS AN EARTH VESSEL.
YOU'RE IN NO POSITION
TO TAKE COMMAND.
T'POL: AS SOON AS
WE'RE THROUGH HERE,
I'LL CONTACT AMBASSADOR SOVAL.
HE'LL SPEAK TO YOUR SUPERIORS,
AND I'M CERTAIN THEY'LL
SUPPORT MY AUTHORITY
IN THIS SITUATION.
TRIP: YOU MUST REALLY BE
PROUD OF YOURSELF.
YOU CAN PUT AN END
TO THIS MISSION
WHILE OUR CAPTAIN'S STILL
UNCONSCIOUS IN SICK BAY.
YOU WON'T EVEN HAVE
TO LOOK HIM IN THE EYE.
T'POL: YOUR PRECIOUS
CARGO WAS STOLEN.
THREE SULIBAN,
PERHAPS MORE, WERE KILLED.
AND CAPTAIN ARCHER
HAS BEEN SERIOUSLY WOUNDED.
IT SEEMS TO ME THIS MISSION
HAS PUT AN END TO ITSELF.
TURN AROUND.
TRIP: LET'S SAY YOU'RE RIGHT.
LET'S SAY WE SCREWED UP, JUST
LIKE YOU ALWAYS KNEW WE WOULD.
IT'S STILL A PRETTY GOOD BET
THAT WHOEVER BLEW THAT HOLE
IN THE CAPTAIN'S LEG
IS CONNECTED SOMEHOW
TO THE PEOPLE THAT TOOK KLAANG.
I FAIL TO SEE YOUR POINT.
TRIP: CAPTAIN ARCHER DESERVES
A CHANCE TO SEE THIS THROUGH.
IF YOU KNEW HIM, YOU'D REALIZE
THAT'S WHAT HE'S ABOUT.
HE NEEDS TO FINISH
WHAT HE STARTS.
HIS DADDY WAS THE SAME WAY.
T'POL: YOU OBVIOUSLY SHARE
YOUR CAPTAIN'S BELIEF
THAT MY PEOPLE
WERE RESPONSIBLE
FOR IMPEDING HENRY ARCHER'S
ACCOMPLISHMENTS.
TRIP: HE ONLY WANTED
TO SEE HIS ENGINE FLY.
THEY NEVER EVEN GAVE HIM
THE CHANCE TO FAIL.
AND HERE YOU ARE,
30 YEARS LATER,
PROVING JUST HOW CONSISTENT
YOU VULCANS CAN BE.
AAH.
VERY NICE, VERY NICE.
YOUR MYOFIBERS
ARE FUSING BEAUTIFULLY.
ARCHER: HOW LONG HAVE --
DOCTOR: LESS THAN SIX HOURS.
I THOUGHT IT BEST
TO KEEP YOU SEDATED
WHILE THE OSMOTIC EEL
CAUTERIZED YOUR WOUND.
THANKS.
HOW YOU DOING, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: WELL, THAT DEPENDS.
WHAT'S BEEN GOING ON
THE LAST SIX HOURS?
T'POL: AS YOUR
HIGHEST-RANKING OFFICER,
I ASSUMED COMMAND
WHILE YOU WERE INCAPACITATED.
ARE WE UNDERWAY?
YOU DIDN'T WASTE MUCH TIME,
DID YOU?
T'POL: IS HE FIT
TO RESUME COMMAND?
AS LONG AS HE RETURNS
FOR MORE EEL THERAPY TOMORROW.
HOW LONG BEFORE
WE GET BACK TO EARTH?
TRIP: EARTH, SIR?
T'POL: WE'RE CURRENTLY
TRACKING THE SULIBAN VESSEL
THAT LEFT RIGEL SHORTLY
AFTER YOU WERE INJURED.
YOU GOT THEIR
PLASMA DECAY RATE?
WITH MR. TUCKER'S ASSISTANCE,
I MODIFIED YOUR SENSORS.
WE NOW HAVE THE RESOLUTION
TO DETECT THEIR WARP TRAIL.
WHAT HAPPENED TO
"THIS IS A FOOLISH MISSION"?
T'POL: THIS IS
A FOOLISH MISSION.
THE SULIBAN ARE CLEARLY
A HOSTILE RACE
WITH TECHNOLOGY
FAR SUPERIOR TO YOURS,
BUT AS ACTING CAPTAIN,
I WAS OBLIGATED
TO ANTICIPATE YOUR WISHES.
AS ACTING CAPTAIN,
YOU COULD HAVE DONE
WHATEVER THE HELL
YOU WANTED TO DO.
I SHOULD RETURN TO THE BRIDGE.
DISMISSED.
TRIP: MODIFYING THE SENSORS
WAS HER IDEA, SIR.
ARCHER: ENTERPRISE STARLOG,
CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER,
APRIL 16, 2151.
WE'VE BEEN TRACKING
THE SULIBAN SHIP FOR 10 HOURS,
THANKS TO OUR SCIENCE OFFICER,
WHO CAME UP WITH A WAY
TO TWEAK THE SENSORS.
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
I SAVE HER LIFE, NOW SHE'S
HELPING US WITH A MISSION.
ONE GOOD TURN DESERVES ANOTHER.
DOESN'T SOUND VERY VULCAN.
RESUME LOG.
I HAVE NO REASON TO BELIEVE
THAT KLAANG IS STILL ALIVE,
BUT IF WHAT THE SULIBAN WOMAN
TOLD ME IS TRUE,
IT'S CRUCIAL
THAT WE TRY TO FIND HIM.
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
HAVE YOU EVER KNOWN A VULCAN
TO RETURN A FAVOR?
NO, NEITHER HAVE I.
RESUME LOG.
I STILL HAVEN'T DECIDED
WHETHER TO ASK
SUBCOMMANDER T'POL
ABOUT THIS TEMPORAL COLD WAR.
MY INSTINCTS TELL ME
NOT TO TRUST HER.
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
ARCHER TO T'POL. REPORT.
T'Pol: If you're
feeling well enough
to come to the bridge, Captain,
now would be a good time.
IT'S A GAS GIANT.
FROM THE LOOKS OF IT,
A CLASS-6 OR -7.
CLASS-7.
THE SULIBAN VESSEL DROPPED
TO IMPULSE A FEW HOURS AGO
AND ALTERED COURSE.
THEIR NEW HEADING TOOK THEM
THROUGH ITS OUTER
RADIATION BELT.
WE'VE LOST THEM.
YES.
[ SIGHS ]
MOVE US IN CLOSER.
ANYTHING?
THE RADIATION'S DISSIPATED
THEIR WARP TRAIL.
I'M ONLY PICKING UP FRAGMENTS.
YOU FINISHED HELPING US?
T'POL: LIEUTENANT,
RUN A SPECTRAL ANALYSIS
OF THE FRAGMENTS.
REED: THERE'S TOO MUCH
DISTORTION.
THE DECAY RATES
DON'T EVEN MATCH.
CALCULATE THE TRAJECTORY
OF EACH FRAGMENT.
REED: SIR?
YOU HEARD HER.
RECALIBRATE THE SENSOR ARRAY,
NARROW BAND,
SHORT- TO MID-RANGE.
REED: AYE, SIR.
MEASURE THE PARTICLE DENSITY
OF THE THERMOSPHERE.
ARCHER: YOUR INSTINCTS
WERE RIGHT.
THOSE FRAGMENTS WEREN'T
FROM ONE SULIBAN SHIP.
THEY WERE FROM 14, AND ALL
WITHIN THE LAST SIX HOURS.
I BELIEVE WE HAVE FOUND
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
HOW ARE YOUR TARGETING SCANNERS?
ALIGNED AND READY, SIR.
BRING THE WEAPONS ONLINE
AND POLARIZE THE HULL PLATING.
LAY IN A 60-DEGREE VECTOR.
WE'RE GOING IN.
ALIEN: DID SARIN
GIVE THEM ANYTHING?
SULIBAN: I DON'T KNOW.
ALIEN: WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
THEY FOLLOWED US HERE.
LOOKING FOR KLAANG OR FOR YOU?
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT I WILL DESTROY THEM
BEFORE THEY LOCATE THE HELIX.
WE DIDN'T PLAN TO INVOLVE
THE HUMANS OR THE VULCANS,
NOT YET.
SARIN'S MESSAGE
CANNOT REACH KRONOS.
IF THE HUMANS HAVE IT,
YOU MUST STOP THEM.
SENSOR RESOLUTION'S FALLING OFF
AT ABOUT 12 KILOMETERS.
TRAVIS?
I'M OK, CAPTAIN.
OUR SITUATION SHOULD IMPROVE.
WE'RE ABOUT TO BREAK THROUGH
THE CYCLOHEXANE LAYER.
I WOULDN'T EXACTLY CALL THIS
AN IMPROVEMENT.
LIQUID PHOSPHOROUS.
I WOULDN'T HAVE EXPECTED THAT
BENEATH A LAYER OF CYCLOHEXANE.
YOU MIGHT THINK
ABOUT RECOMMENDING SEAT
BELTS WHEN WE GET HOME.
IT'S JUST A LITTLE BAD WEATHER.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
WE'VE GOT SENSORS.
LEVEL OFF.
GO TO LONG-RANGE SCANS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
I'M DETECTING TWO VESSELS,
BEARING 119 MARK 7.
PUT IT UP.
REED: IMPULSE AND WARP ENGINES.
ARCHER: WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS?
WE'RE TOO FAR AWAY.
TRAVIS: SIR, I'M PICKING UP
SOMETHING AT 342 MARK 12.
IT'S A LOT BIGGER.
ALL SENSORS,
GET WHATEVER YOU CAN.
GO TIGHTER.
ARCHER: BIO-SIGNS?
OVER 30,000, BUT I CAN'T ISOLATE
A KLINGON IF THERE IS ONE.
[ RUMBLING, COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THAT WAS A PARTICLE WEAPON, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TRIP: BRIDGE, WE'RE
TAKING DAMAGE DOWN HERE.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
JUST A LITTLE TROUBLE
WITH THE BAD GUYS.
I SUGGEST WE RETURN
TO THE PHOSPHOROUS LAYER.
TAKE US UP.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
T'POL: IT APPEARS TO BE
AN AGGREGATE STRUCTURE
COMPRISED OF HUNDREDS
OF VESSELS.
THEY'RE HELD IN PLACE
BY AN INTERLOCKING SYSTEM
OF MAGNETIC SEALS.
THERE. RIGHT THERE.
THESE BIO-READINGS
ARE NOT SULIBAN.
WE CAN'T BE CERTAIN
THEY'RE KLINGON.
EVEN IF IT IS KLAANG,
WE'D HAVE A TOUGH TIME
GETTING HIM OUT OF THERE.
WE COULD ALWAYS TRY
THE TRANSPORTING DEVICE.
WE'VE RISKED TOO MUCH
TO BRING HIM BACK INSIDE-OUT.
WOULD THE GRAPPLER WORK
IN A LIQUID ATMOSPHERE?
I BELIEVE SO.
BRING IT ONLINE.
ONE MORE TIME, MR. MAYWEATHER.
REED: THE VENTRAL
PLATING'S DOWN.
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
LEAD SHIP'S CLOSING.
7,000 METERS.
6,000.
WE SHOULD ASCEND.
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
REED: 1,000 METERS.
FORWARD PLATING'S OFFLINE.
NOW, MR. REED.
THE SHIP'S IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
TRIP: ASK ME ANOTHER ONE.
TRAVIS:
ALL RIGHT. WHAT'S THIS?
TRIP: THE PITCH CONTROL.
NO, THAT'S THE PITCH CONTROL.
THIS IS THE GUIDANCE SYSTEM.
TRIP: PITCH CONTROL,
GUIDANCE SYSTEM.
GOT IT.
THE DOCKING INTERFACE --
HOW DO YOU DEPLOY IT?
RELEASE THE INERTIAL CLAMPS
HERE, HERE, AND HERE,
THEN INITIALIZE
THE COAXIAL PORTS.
GOOD. WHERE'S
THE AUXILIARY THROTTLE?
TRIP: HMM.
IT'S NOT THIS ONE.
TRAVIS: WITH ALL DUE RESPECT
TO COMMANDER TUCKER,
I'M PRETTY SURE
I CAN FLY THIS THING, SIR.
I DON'T DOUBT THAT,
BUT I NEED YOU HERE.
TRIP: THERE, THAT'S IT.
AUXILIARY THROTTLE.
[ RUMBLING ]
CAPTAIN, THAT CHARGE CONTAINED
A PROXIMITY SWEEP.
IF WE REMAIN HERE,
THEY'RE GOING TO LOCATE US.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO SPEED
THIS UP A LITTLE, TRAVIS.
TRIP: HOW COMPLICATED CAN IT BE?
UP, DOWN, FORWARD, REVERSE --
WE'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
WE'LL BE BACK
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT.
HAVE MAYWEATHER PLOT
A COURSE FOR KRONOS.
THERE'S A VULCAN SHIP
LESS THAN TWO DAYS AWAY.
IT'S ILLOGICAL
TO ATTEMPT THIS ALONE.
I WAS BEGINNING TO THINK
YOU UNDERSTOOD
WHY WE HAVE TO DO THIS ALONE.
YOU'LL HAVE OTHER OPPORTUNITIES
TO DEMONSTRATE
YOUR INDEPENDENCE.
NEVER PUT OFF TILL TOMORROW.
YOU BOTH COULD BE KILLED.
AM I SENSING CONCERN?
LAST TIME I CHECKED,
THAT WAS CONSIDERED AN EMOTION.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS
TO EITHER OF YOU,
THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
WILL HOLD ME RESPONSIBLE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
ARCHER: COME IN.
YOU FINISHED?
REED: SIR.
THIS SHOULD REVERSE
THE POLARITY OF ANY MAG LOCK
WITHIN A HUNDRED METERS.
ONCE YOU'VE SET THE SEQUENCE,
YOU'LL HAVE FIVE SECONDS.
ONE MORE THING.
AH, OUR NEW WEAPONS.
THEY'RE CALLED PHASE PISTOLS.
THEY HAVE TWO SETTINGS --
STUN AND KILL.
IT WOULD BE BEST
NOT TO CONFUSE THEM.
[ RUMBLING ]
TIME TO GO.
THE SHIP IS YOURS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WHAT'S THAT?
TRAVIS SAID NOT TO WORRY
ABOUT THAT PANEL.
THAT'S REASSURING.
HOLD ON.
THAT WAS A LOT CLOSER.
IF WE CHANGE OUR POSITION,
THEY'LL HAVE TO START
FROM SCRATCH.
IF WE CHANGE OUR POSITION,
THE CAPTAIN WILL HAVE NO WAY
OF FINDING US.
I THINK WE'RE THERE.
BRING THE DOCKING INTERFACE
ONLINE.
THE COAXIAL PORTS.
OPEN.
LET'S GO.
WHERE IS IT?
IT WAS RIGHT THERE.
BANK STARBOARD, 90 DEGREES.
TRIP: THERE YOU ARE.
THAT'S THE UPPER SUPPORT RADIUS.
DROP DOWN RIGHT BELOW IT.
START A COUNTERCLOCKWISE SWEEP.
A LITTLE MORE.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
RIGHT THERE.
ARCHER: STUN SEEMS TO WORK.
GRAB ONTO SOMETHING!
[ ALARMS BLARING ]
THIS IS RIDICULOUS!
IF WE DON'T MOVE THE SHIP,
CAPTAIN ARCHER WON'T HAVE
ANYTHING TO LOOK FOR
WHEN HE GETS BACK.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
THAT EAR OF YOURS.
MOVE US AWAY FIVE KILOMETERS.
IN WHAT DIRECTION?
ANY DIRECTION.
THIS IS GONNA BE EASIER
THAN I THOUGHT.
IT'S OK.
WE'RE GETTING YOU
OFF THIS THING.
[ GROWLING ]
I REALLY DON'T WANT TO HAVE
TO CARRY YOU OUT OF HERE.
YOU OK?
I THINK HE GETS THE IDEA.
GIVE HIM A HAND.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
BE QUIET.
YOU TELL HIM, BIG GUY.
GIVE ME THE BOX!
[ GRUNTING ]
THANKS.
ARCHER: GET TO THE SHIP.
I'LL BE RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
[ ELECTRONIC WHINE ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
CAPTAIN?
Archer: It worked, Trip.
WHERE ARE YOU?
STILL IN THE CENTRAL CORE.
GET KLAANG BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, SIR?
Archer: Get him to the ship.
You can come back for me.
IT'S GONNA BE HARD
TO ISOLATE YOUR BIO-SIGNS,
SO STAY AS FAR AWAY
FROM THE SULIBAN AS YOU CAN.
BELIEVE ME, I'LL TRY.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
I DON'T PARTICULARLY LIKE
THE WAY YOU SMELL, EITHER!
I DON'T GET IT.
THIS IS RIGHT WHERE
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE.
THE CHARGES
ARE GETTING CLOSER AGAIN.
ANOTHER FIVE KILOMETERS, ENSIGN.
AT THIS RATE,
THE CAPTAIN WILL NEVER FIND US.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I THINK I'VE GOT SOMETHING.
AMPLIFY IT.
[ Static ]
IT'S COMMANDER TUCKER.
ALL I HEAR IS NOISE.
IT'S JUST A NARROW NOTCH
IN THE MID-RANGE.
HE SAYS HE'S ABOUT TO IGNITE
HIS THRUSTER EXHAUST.
COORDINATES 158 MARK 13.
TRAVIS: LAID IN.
AHEAD, 50 KPH.
[ SPEAKING VULCAN ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
TWO KILOMETERS, DEAD AHEAD.
INITIATE DOCKING PROCEDURES.
I'M ONLY PICKING UP
TWO BIO-SIGNS.
ONE KLINGON, ONE HUMAN.
[ FOOTSTEPS ECHOING ]
TURN THIS SHIP AROUND NOW.
OUR MISSION IS TO RETURN
THE KLINGON TO HIS HOMEWORLD.
ANOTHER RESCUE ATTEMPT COULD
JEOPARDIZE THAT MISSION.
THE CAPTAIN SPECIFICALLY TOLD US
TO COME BACK FOR HIM.
AS COMMANDING OFFICER,
IT'S MY JOB TO INTERPRET
THE CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
I JUST TOLD YOU HIS ORDERS!
WHAT'S THERE TO INTERPRET?
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER
MAY VERY WELL
HAVE TOLD YOU TO RETURN
FOR HIM LATER
BECAUSE HE KNEW
HOW STUBBORN YOU CAN BE.
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
YOU MIGHT HAVE
RISKED KLAANG'S LIFE
IN A FOOLISH ATTEMPT TO SWING
BACK AND RESCUE THE CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS!
[ RUMBLING ]
THE SITUATION MUST
BE ANALYZED LOGICALLY.
I DON'T REMEMBER
THE CAPTAIN ANALYZING ANYTHING
WHEN HE WENT BACK FOR YOU
ON THAT ROOF.
THAT IS A SPECIOUS ANALOGY.
IS IT?
ALIEN, ECHOING:
YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME.
KLAANG KNOWS NOTHING.
IT WOULD BE UNWISE TO DISCHARGE
THAT WEAPON IN THIS ROOM.
ARCHER, ECHOING:
WHAT IS THIS ROOM?
WHAT GOES ON HERE?
ALIEN: YOU'RE VERY CURIOUS, JON.
MAY I CALL YOU JON?
AM I SUPPOSED TO BE IMPRESSED
YOU KNOW MY NAME?
ALIEN: I'VE LEARNED A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT YOU --
EVEN MORE THAN YOU KNOW.
WELL, I GUESS YOU HAVE ME
AT A DISADVANTAGE.
SO WHY DON'T YOU DROP
THIS INVISIBLE-MAN ROUTINE
AND LET ME SEE
WHO I'M TALKING TO?
HULL PLATING'S
BEEN REPOLARIZED.
STAND BY IMPULSE ENGINES.
MR. TUCKER, STATUS?
THE AUTO-SEQUENCER'S ONLINE,
BUT ANNULAR CONFINEMENT'S
STILL OFF BY TWO MICRONS.
T'Pol: That should suffice.
EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
IF THE SULIBAN HAVE
REESTABLISHED THEIR DEFENSES,
WE'LL HAVE NO OTHER OPTION.
ALIEN: YOU WOULDN'T HAVE
COME LOOKING FOR KLAANG
IF SARIN HAD TOLD YOU
WHAT SHE KNEW.
THAT MEANS YOU'RE
NO THREAT TO ME, JON,
BUT I DO NEED YOU
TO LEAVE THIS ROOM...
NOW.
ARCHER: THIS CHAMELEON THING
IS PRETTY FANCY.
WAS IT PAYMENT FOR PITTING
THE KLINGONS AGAINST EACH OTHER
OR A TROPHY FROM
YOUR TEMPORAL COLD WAR?
UHH!
ALIEN: I WAS GOING
TO LET YOU GO.
ARCHER: REALLY?
THEN YOU OBVIOUSLY
DON'T KNOW AS MUCH ABOUT ME
AS YOU THOUGHT YOU DID.
ALIEN: ON THE CONTRARY.
I COULD'VE TOLD YOU WHAT DAY
YOU WERE GOING TO DIE,
BUT I SUPPOSE THAT'S
ABOUT TO CHANGE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE MATTER?
NO GENETIC TRICKS TO
KEEP YOU FROM GETTING
KNOCKED ON YOUR BUTT?
ALIEN: WHAT YOU CALL TRICKS,
WE CALL PROGRESS.
ARE YOU AWARE
THAT YOUR GENOME
IS ALMOST IDENTICAL
TO THAT OF AN APE?
THE SULIBAN DON'T SHARE
HUMANITY'S PATIENCE
WITH NATURAL SELECTION.
ARCHER: SO TO SPEED
THINGS UP A LITTLE,
YOU STRUCK A DEAL
WITH THE DEVIL?
WE HAVE FOUR MORE
COMING UP ON STARBOARD.
CAN WE DOCK, ENSIGN?
THESE AREN'T IDEAL CONDITIONS.
MR. TUCKER,
WE'RE GOING TO PLAN "B."
NOW!
BRIDGE, WE'VE GOT HIM.
SORRY, CAPTAIN.
WE HAD NO OTHER CHOICE.
[ BELL TOLLING ]
[ MEN SHOUTING IN KLINGON ]
[ POUNDING ON DOOR ]
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
SOMETHING ABOUT
DISGRACING THE EMPIRE.
HE SAYS HE'S READY TO DIE.
[ GASPS ]
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A THANK YOU.
I DON'T THINK THEY HAVE
A WORD FOR "THANK YOU."
WHAT DID HE SAY?
YOU DON'T WANT TO KNOW.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
JUST GOTTEN A RESPONSE
TO THE MESSAGE I SENT
TO ADMIRAL FORREST.
HE ENJOYED TELLING
THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
ABOUT THE SULIBAN WE RAN INTO.
IT ISN'T EVERY DAY
HE GETS TO BE THE ONE
DISPENSING INFORMATION.
I WANTED YOU BOTH
TO HEAR STARFLEET'S ORDERS
BEFORE I INFORM THE CREW.
TRIP: ORDERS?
YOUR PEOPLE ARE SENDING
A TRANSPORT TO PICK YOU UP.
T'POL: I WAS UNDER
THE IMPRESSION
THAT ENTERPRISE WOULD BE
TAKING ME BACK TO EARTH.
IT WOULD BE
A LITTLE OUT OF OUR WAY.
ADMIRAL FORREST SEES NO REASON
WHY WE SHOULDN'T KEEP GOING.
TRIP: SON OF A BITCH.
I HAVE A FEELING DR. PHLOX WON'T
MIND STAYING AROUND FOR A WHILE.
HE'S DEVELOPING A FONDNESS
FOR THE HUMAN ENDOCRINE SYSTEM.
TRIP: I'LL GET DOUBLE SHIFTS
ON THE REPAIR WORK.
I THINK THAT OUTER HULL'S
GONNA NEED A LITTLE PATCHING UP.
LET'S HOPE THAT'S THE LAST TIME
SOMEBODY TAKES A SHOT AT US.
LET'S HOPE.
ARCHER: T'POL.
WOULD YOU STICK AROUND
FOR A MINUTE?
EVER SINCE I CAN REMEMBER,
I'VE SEEN VULCANS
AS AN OBSTACLE,
ALWAYS KEEPING US FROM
STANDING ON OUR OWN TWO FEET.
I UNDERSTAND.
NO, I DON'T THINK YOU DO.
IF I'M GONNA PULL THIS OFF,
THERE ARE A FEW THINGS
I NEED TO LEAVE BEHIND --
THINGS LIKE PRECONCEPTIONS,
HOLDING GRUDGES.
THIS MISSION WOULD'VE FAILED
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
I WON'T DISPUTE THAT.
I WAS THINKING.
A VULCAN SCIENCE OFFICER
COULD COME IN HANDY.
BUT IF I ASK YOU TO STAY,
IT MIGHT LOOK LIKE I WASN'T
READY TO DO THIS ON MY OWN.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
ADD PRIDE TO YOUR LIST.
PERHAPS I SHOULD.
IT MIGHT BE BEST IF
I WERE TO CONTACT MY SUPERIORS
AND MAKE THE REQUEST MYSELF...
WITH YOUR PERMISSION.
PERMISSION GRANTED.
I HOPE NOBODY IS
IN A BIG HURRY TO GET HOME.
STARFLEET SEEMS TO THINK
THAT WE'RE READY
TO BEGIN OUR MISSION.
I UNDERSTAND THERE'S
AN INHABITED PLANET
A FEW LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE.
REED: WE'VE DETECTED IT, SIR.
SENSORS SHOW
A NITROGEN-SULFIDE ATMOSPHERE.
PROBABLY NOT HUMANOIDS.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE HERE
TO FIND OUT.
PREPARE TO BREAK ORBIT
AND LAY IN A COURSE.
I'M READING AN ION STORM
ON THAT TRAJECTORY, SIR.
SHOULD I GO AROUND IT?
WE CAN'T BE AFRAID
OF THE WIND, ENSIGN.
TAKE US TO WARP 4.