[ CLICKING TONGUE ]
PHLOX: I DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU SPOKE SLUG.
I WISH I DID.
SHE DOESN'T LOOK ANY BETTER,
DOES SHE?
PHLOX: SHE?
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO DETERMINE ITS GENDER,
IF IT HAS ONE.
HOSHI: I SHOULD HAVE LEFT HER
WHERE I FOUND HER.
PHLOX: NONSENSE. YOU'RE
ON A MISSION OF EXPLORATION.
THERE'S SOMETHING TO BE LEARNED
FROM EVERY LIFE-FORM.
SHE WASN'T MEANT TO BE
IN THIS ENVIRONMENT.
PHLOX: I PROMISE TO DO MY BEST
TO KEEP IT ALIVE.
HE'S GONNA MAKE YOU ALL BETTER.
PHLOX: ACTUALLY, I WAS THINKING
MORE ABOUT MY PYRITHIAN BAT.
HE WON'T EAT ANYTHING
ONCE IT'S DEAD, HMM?
TUCKER: WE'VE ROUTED SOME MORE
POWER TO SICK BAY.
LET ME KNOW IF IT'S ENOUGH.
PHLOX: THIS SHOULD DO FINE.
TUCKER: HOW'S SLUGGO?
HOSHI: DR. PHLOX THINKS
THIS ARGON LAMP SHOULD HELP.
SHE'S BARELY MOVED ALL DAY.
TUCKER: WE'VE BEEN OUT HERE
FOR TWO WEEKS,
AND THE ONLY FIRST CONTACT
WE'VE MADE
IS WITH A DYING WORM.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ SQUEAK ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
T'POL: THE SCANS OF THE SECTORS
AHEAD--
ARCHER: SHH!
HEAR THAT?
T'POL: HEAR WHAT?
ARCHER: A SQUEAK.
SOMETHING SQUEAKING.
I THINK IT'S COMING
FROM UNDER THE DECK PLATING,
BUT EVERY TIME I GET CLOSE
TO IT, IT STOPS.
IF I CAN'T ISOLATE IT,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO TEAR
THE WHOLE FLOORING UP.
THAT WOULD BE UNFORTUNATE.
THE SCANS OF THE SECTORS AHEAD
INDICATE LITTLE CHANCE
OF FINDING INHABITED PLANETS.
ARCHER: WELL, HOW ABOUT
THE VULCAN STARCHARTS?
T'POL: WE HAVE LIMITED DATA
ON THE COURSE THAT STARFLEET
ASSIGNED YOU.
THERE ARE THOUSANDS
OF STAR SYSTEMS ALONG THIS PATH.
THERE MUST HAVE BEEN SOMETHING
THAT PIQUED
YOUR PEOPLE'S INTEREST--
A SENTIENT SPECIES,
A TRINARY STAR CLUSTER.
T'POL: WE DON'T SELECT
OUR DESTINATIONS
BY WHAT PIQUES OUR INTEREST.
VULCANS ALWAYS NEED
A LOGICAL AND PRAGMATIC REASON.
T'POL: MY PEOPLE DON'T SHARE
YOUR ENTHUSIASM FOR EXPLORATION.
[ SQUEAKING ]
T'POL: SPACE IS VAST, CAPTAIN.
I'M SURE YOU'RE AWARE
THAT ONLY ONE OUT OF
EVERY 43,000 PLANETS
SUPPORTS INTELLIGENT LIFE.
ARCHER: I TOOK EXOBIOLOGY.
I KNOW THE STATISTICS.
BUT WE'RE TRAVELING AT WARP 5.
THERE'S GOT TO BE
SOMEONE OUT HERE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
HOSHI: I'M SORRY.
T'POL: I'LL LEAVE YOU
TO YOUR EXPLORING.
ARCHER: TRIP TELLS ME
THAT SLUGGO'S NOT
FARING TOO WELL.
HOSHI: NO, SIR, BUT THE DOCTOR'S
DOING THE BEST HE CAN.
SIR, MY QUARTERS
ARE ON "E" DECK,
STARBOARD SECTION 5.
YES.
THE STARS ARE GOING
THE WRONG WAY, SIR.
WRONG WAY?
ON BOTH MY TRAINING TOURS,
I HAD PORT-SIDE QUARTERS.
I'M HAVING TROUBLE SLEEPING.
BECAUSE YOU'RE ON
THE WRONG SIDE--
THE WRONG SIDE OF THE SHIP,
YES, SIR.
I SPOKE WITH ENSIGN PORTER.
HE SAID HE'D BE WILLING
TO SWITCH WITH YOUR PERMISSION.
YOU GOT IT.
CAN'T HAVE MY COM OFFICER
FALLING ASLEEP ON THE BRIDGE.
APPRECIATE IT, CAPTAIN.
IS THERE SOMETHING ELSE, HOSHI?
NO, SIR. THANK YOU.
[ SQUEAK ]
READY?
TRAVIS: FORE AND AFT
TARGET SCANNERS ARE ALIGNED.
REED: ACTIVATING SIMULATION J-6.
REED: TARGET ACQUIRED.
TRAVIS: SIMULATED LAUNCH.
FIVE SECONDS TO IMPACT.
THREE, TWO, ONE.
REED: WONDERFUL.
TRAVIS: WE'RE ONLY OFF
BY THREE METERS.
REED: ONLY THREE METERS?
THREE METERS COULD MEAN
THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN HITTING A WEAPONS PORT
AND A WARP CORE.
INSTEAD OF DISABLING A VESSEL,
WE'D END UP DESTROYING IT,
AND PROBABLY OURSELVES
IN THE PROCESS.
TRAVIS: WE'LL GET IT RIGHT.
REED: ALL THIS SHOULD HAVE BEEN
DEALT WITH BEFORE WE LEFT EARTH.
HAVE THEY DETECTED ANY INHABITED
PLANETS OR VESSELS?
TRAVIS: NOT YET.
REED: GOOD.
TRAVIS: I HOPE YOU DON'T
EXPECT EVERYONE
WE RUN INTO OUT HERE
TO BE HOSTILE.
IN 23 YEARS, I DON'T THINK
MY FOLKS RAN INTO PROBLEMS
MORE THAN A HALF-DOZEN TIMES.
REED: I DON'T BELIEVE YOU WERE
EVER OUT QUITE THIS FAR.
TRAVIS: DO YOU THINK
THAT MAKES A DIFFERENCE?
REED: ALL I DO KNOW
IS THAT UNTIL WE GET
THESE TARGETING SCANNERS
WORKING PROPERLY,
THE FARTHER WE ARE
FROM EVERYONE ELSE, THE BETTER.
[ TRAVIS CHUCKLES ]
SEEMS LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE
ONBOARD
IS ITCHING FOR A FIRST CONTACT.
ARCHER: HOW'S IT GOING?
REED: NOT WELL, SIR.
WE'VE CORRECTED THE PROBLEM,
BUT WE'RE STILL OFF BY .02%.
IT'S UNACCEPTABLE.
ARCHER: ARE YOU SURE IT'S NOT
THE SIMULATIONS THAT ARE OFF?
REED: THERE'S ONLY
ONE WAY TO FIND OUT.
ARCHER: HOW LONG WOULD IT TAKE
TO ARM A FEW TORPEDOES?
REED: MOMENTS, SIR.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'POL: YES, SIR.
ARCHER: PREPARE TO
DROP OUT OF WARP.
IT'S TIME FOR A LITTLE
TARGET PRACTICE.
T'POL: ACKNOWLEDGED.
REED: THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
COME ON, TRAVIS.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND MR. REED
SOMETHING TO BLOW UP.
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER: LOAD ANOTHER ONE.
LET'S TRY AGAIN.
REED: ROTATE THE TARGETING AXIS
BY .5 MICRONS.
TRAVIS: .5 MICRONS.
MR. REED.
REED: IF I REFOCUS
THE INFRARED SCANNER,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO COMPENSATE.
HOW LONG WILL THAT TAKE?
THE BETTER PART OF A DAY.
ARCHER: RESUME COURSE, ENSIGN.
REED: SIR.
ARCHER: WE'RE NOT GONNA SIT
ON OUR BUTT FOR 24 HOURS.
MAKE YOUR MODIFICATIONS.
WE'LL RUN ANOTHER TEST
FIRST CHANCE WE GET.
TUCKER: ANYONE SITTING HERE?
PHLOX: NO. PLEASE SIT DOWN.
SIT DOWN.
TUCKER: SLUGGO ANY BETTER?
PHLOX: I'M AFRAID NOT.
TRY THE POTATOES.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
RESEQUENCED PROTEIN.
YES.
THE FLAVOR'S REMARKABLE.
ON MY HOMEWORLD,
PEOPLE WOULD NEVER THINK
OF SPEAKING DURING A MEAL.
CONSIDER IT A WASTE OF TIME.
[ CHUCKLES ]
IT'S TAKEN ME A WHILE,
BUT I'VE GROWN
QUITE ATTACHED TO IT.
TUCKER: WASTING TIME SEEMS
TO BE ALL WE'VE BEEN DOING.
STARTING TO GET A LITTLE ANTSY.
PHLOX: ANTSY?
TUCKER: RESTLESS.
PHLOX: MM.
TUCKER: WE'VE BEEN ON THE MOVE
FOR TWO WEEKS
AND HAVEN'T SEEN A DAMN THING.
[ PHLOX CHUCKLES ]
EVERY MOMENT'S BEEN
AN ADVENTURE FOR ME.
HUMANS ARE SO UNPREDICTABLE.
HAVE YOU SEEN THE QUANTITIES
OF FOOD CREWMAN NAMOD CONSUMES?
NOT REALLY.
HAVE YOU SMELLED ENSIGN SOCORRO
AFTER SHE EXERCISES?
UH...
PHLOX: SHE GIVES OFF A FRAGRANCE
NOT UNLIKE THE ADRENAL GLAND
OF A NAUSICAAN.
AND CREWMEN BENNETT
AND HAYDEN OVER THERE--
DO YOU SEE THEM?
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN, THEY ARE
PREPARING TO MATE.
DO YOU THINK THEY MIGHT
LET ME WATCH?
IT'S GOOD TO SEE
YOU'RE ENJOYING YOURSELF.
MMM. MMM!
[ BEEPING ]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: HOW BIG IS IT?
T'POL: APPROXIMATELY 92 METERS
IN LENGTH.
ARCHER: DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE MOVING VERY FAST.
T'POL: IT'S NOT MOVING AT ALL.
ARCHER: THAT'S ODD.
WHERE'S THE NEAREST STAR SYSTEM?
T'POL: ALMOST THREE
LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
THEY COULD BE RUNNING SOME KIND
OF A DEEP-SPACE EXPERIMENT.
MAYBE WE SHOULD GO HAVE A LOOK.
T'POL: IF YOU INSIST ON
ALLOWING YOUR CURIOSITY
TO DICTATE YOUR ACTIONS.
WE INSIST.
TRAVIS: RANGE--5,000 KILOMETERS.
T'POL: THE VESSEL'S HULL
IS COMPRISED
OF TRITANIUM
AND DISILICON POLYMERS.
TUCKER: I'M NOT GETTING ANYTHING
ON THEIR PROPULSION SYSTEM.
BUT IT MAY BE OFFLINE.
IT'S SOMETHING, ISN'T IT?
REED: IF THEY HAVE WEAPONS,
THEY'RE NOT CHARGED.
ARCHER: ANY COM ACTIVITY?
[ BEEPING ]
HOSHI: NO, SIR.
ARCHER: RUN THIS THROUGH
THE TRANSLATION MATRIX.
MY NAME IS JONATHAN ARCHER.
I'M CAPTAIN
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
WE'RE ON A MISSION
OF PEACEFUL EXPLORATION.
MAN: EARTH.
ARCHER: OH.
WE COME FROM THE PLANET EARTH.
WE ARE SENDING YOU A PULSAR GRID
THAT SHOULD HELP YOU
LOCATE OUR STAR SYSTEM.
DID YOU ROTATE THE FREQUENCIES?
I'LL TRY IT AGAIN.
NO RESPONSE, SIR.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN,
MIND IF I PUSH IN
ON THE VENTING PORTS
AROUND THAT HATCH?
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
TRAVIS: ARE THOSE VENTING PORTS
OR HULL BREACHES?
ARCHER: BRING US IN
A LITTLE CLOSER, TRAVIS.
LET'S GET A LOOK
AT THE OTHER SIDE.
ARCHER: THOSE LOOK
LIKE SCORCH MARKS.
THE RESIDUE INDICATES OXIDATION
AND THERMAL SHOCK EFFECTS.
IT COULD BE THE RESULT
OF A HIGH-YIELD PARTICLE IMPACT.
YOU MEAN WEAPONS.
POSSIBLY.
ARE WE CLOSE ENOUGH
TO SCAN FOR BIO-SIGNS?
T'POL: YES, BUT SCANNING
THEIR SHIP'S INTERIOR
MIGHT BE SEEN
AS A VIOLATION OF PRIVACY.
ANYTHING?
TUCKER: IF THERE IS ANYONE HOME,
YOU CAN BET THEY KNOW
WE'RE OUT HERE.
REED: THEN WHY HAVEN'T
THEY RESPONDED?
T'POL: NOT EVERYONE
CHOOSES TO ANSWER THE DOOR
WHEN THEY HEAR A KNOCK.
IT WOULD BE BEST TO RESUME
OUR PREVIOUS COURSE.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND
ANOTHER HATCH.
ARCHER: DIAMETER?
TUCKER: .9 METERS.
ARCHER: SCAN FOR BIO-SIGNS.
THERE ARE A NUMBER
OF LIFE-FORMS ABOARD.
ARCHER: HUMANOID?
THEIR CELLULAR ACTIVITY
IS BELOW
THE THRESHOLD OF YOUR SENSORS.
TRAVIS: MAYBE THEY'RE
IN TROUBLE--SICK OR SOMETHING.
MAYBE THEY'RE NOT INTERESTED
IN VISITORS.
ARCHER: MR. REED, HOW LONG
TO PREP A SHUTTLE?
REED: HALF AN HOUR.
T'POL: THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
PROTOCOLS WE HAVEN'T TRIED.
ARCHER: GET STARTED.
HOSHI: SHE MAY HAVE
A POINT, CAPTAIN.
I COULD TRY HAILING THEM
ON THE THETA-BAND FREQUENCIES.
ARCHER: SUIT UP, ENSIGN.
ME, SIR?
ARCHER: SHIP IS YOURS.
ARCHER: IS THERE
A PROBLEM, COMMANDER?
TUCKER: I WANT TO GO WITH YOU.
ARCHER: I'M BRINGING
A TRANSLATOR
AND A SECURITY OFFICER.
WHY WOULD I NEED
AN ENGINEER?
TUCKER: WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU CAN OPEN THE HATCH
OR TURN THE LIGHTS ON,
FOR THAT MATTER?
ARCHER: WE'VE GOT BEACONS, TRIP.
TUCKER: WELL, THAT SHIP COULD
HAVE A LOT OF DECKS.
YOU MIGHT NEED SOMEBODY TO HELP
YOU FIGURE OUT THE TURBOLIFTS.
OKAY, I'VE GOT A BETTER REASON
WHY YOU NEED AN ENGINEER.
'CAUSE YOUR ENGINEER
SIGNED ONTO THIS
MISSION OF EXPLORATION
SO HE COULD DO
A LITTLE EXPLORING.
HE DIDN'T SIGN ON
SO HE COULD SIT IN ENGINEERING
WHILE YOU THREE GET
TO BREAK INTO THAT SHIP.
ARCHER: WE'RE NOT BREAKING IN.
WE'RE JUST GOING TO SEE
IF EVERYTHING'S OKAY.
TUCKER: YOU'RE CHOMPING AT THE
BIT TO FIND OUT WHAT'S IN THERE.
WHY SHOULD I BE ANY DIFFERENT?
ARCHER: WE JUST
GOT OUT HERE, TRIP.
THERE'S GONNA BE PLENTY OF TIME
TO GO EXPLORING.
RIGHT NOW,
I NEED YOU ON ENTERPRISE
DOWN WITH YOUR ENGINE.
THE SHIP'S A LITTLE YOUNG TO BE
WITHOUT HER CHIEF ENGINEER.
WHEN I USED TO DREAM
ABOUT THIS MISSION,
THE LAST THING I ENVISIONED
WAS HAVING A VULCAN ONBOARD
WHO CONTINUOUSLY SUCKED
THE AIR OUT OF THE ROOM.
WELL...SHE'S RIGHT.
WHOEVER'S ON THAT SHIP
MIGHT NOT WANT US NOSING AROUND.
BUT I CAN'T ASSUME
THAT'S THE CASE, CAN I?
MAYBE THEY COULD USE OUR HELP.
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
YOU KNOW. HEY.
YOU KNOW THAT YOU AND CHEDDAR
DON'T GET ALONG.
AH.
RESUME PERSONAL LOG.
BEFORE WE LEFT,
ADMIRAL FORREST SAID
WE'D BE MAKING HISTORY
WITH EVERY LIGHT-YEAR,
BUT WE'RE NOT GONNA DO THAT
SITTING ON OUR HANDS.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
COME IN.
ARCHER: ENSIGN.
HOSHI: SORRY TO BOTHER YOU, SIR.
ARCHER: IT'S NOT A PROBLEM.
CHEESE?
NO, THANK YOU.
EVERYTHING WORK OUT
ALL RIGHT?
SIR?
WITH THE SWAPPING QUARTERS?
HOSHI: YES, IT'S FINE.
THANK YOU.
I WAS THINKING, CAPTAIN,
I MIGHT BE
A LOT MORE HELPFUL TO YOU
IF I STAY HERE
AND KEEP AN OPEN COM LINK.
THAT WAY, I'LL HAVE
IMMEDIATE ACCESS
TO THE LINGUISTIC DATABASE.
CAN'T YOU TIE
YOUR UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR
INTO THE DATABASE
THROUGH THE COM?
IT'S NOT THE SAME.
THE LAG TIME IS TRIPLED.
WELL, I'D RATHER
WAIT A FEW SECONDS
IF IT MEANS HAVING YOU ON SITE.
FOR ALL WE KNOW,
THE U.T. WON'T WORK.
YOU'LL BE OUR ONLY BACKUP.
ANYWAY, IT SHOULD BE EXCITING.
HALF THE CREW WOULD GIVE THEIR
EYETEETH TO BE GOING OVER THERE.
WHAT'S WRONG?
THE ENVIRONMENTAL SUITS.
THEY MAKE ME
A LITTLE...CLAUSTROPHOBIC.
CLAUSTROPHOBIC?
AND YOU TOOK A JOB
ON A SPACESHIP?
HOSHI: YOU TALKED ME
INTO IT, REMEMBER?
ARCHER: I DON'T RECALL READING
ABOUT ANY PROBLEMS
DURING YOUR ZERO-G TRAINING.
HOSHI: OH, I JUST--I-I BIT
MY LIP AND GOT THROUGH IT.
WELL, YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO BITE YOUR LIP AGAIN.
I NEED YOU OVER THERE.
YES, SIR.
WHAT IS IT, HOSHI?
IS SOMETHING ELSE WRONG?
NO. I'D BETTER GET BACK
TO THE LAUNCH BAY.
ARCHER: HANG ON,
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
[ PORTHOS BARKS ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
ARCHER: THAT'S
THE LAST TIME, PORTHOS.
ARCHER: GOING TO WAR,
LIEUTENANT?
REED: CAN'T BE TOO CAREFUL, SIR.
ARCHER: YOU'VE SEEN TOO MANY
SCIENCE-FICTION MOVIES.
WE JUST NEED
THE THREE PHASE PISTOLS.
PUT THE RIFLES BACK.
WHAT ARE YOU RATED FOR?
HOSHI: I'VE BEEN CLEARED
ON EM SIDEARMS
AND CLASS-3 PULSE RIFLES.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE OF THOSE.
ARCHER: MALCOLM WILL CHECK YOU
OUT ON IT FIRST CHANCE HE GETS.
DON'T WORRY. IT HANDLES
PRETTY MUCH LIKE AN EM-33.
HOSHI: IS THIS NECESSARY?
ARCHER: JUST A PRECAUTION.
JUST OUR LUCK.
NO RELEASE.
SHOULDN'T BE A PROBLEM, THOUGH.
I CAN PLACE MICROCHARGES
HERE AND HERE.
HOLD ON A SECOND, MALCOLM.
SORRY.
HOSHI: ENTERPRISE,
WE'VE GOT ACCESS.
WE'RE BOARDING THE VESSEL.
[ BEEPING ]
HOSHI: WELL, AT LEAST WE KNOW
THEY'RE BIPEDS.
REED: WHAT GIVES YOU THAT IDEA?
HOSHI: THE LADDER.
ARCHER: COME ON.
NITROGEN-METHANE ATMOSPHERE...
AND IT'S COLD--
MINUS-20 DEGREES.
HOSHI: THERE'S POWER
GOING THROUGH HERE,
BUT NOT MUCH OF IT.
REED: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: MOLECULES LOOK
LIKE AMINO ACIDS.
HOSHI: BLOOD?
[ WHIRRING ]
REED: SOME SORT OF HYDRAULICS.
ARCHER: WHATEVER IT IS,
IT HASN'T BEEN HERE VERY LONG.
AAH!
[ HOSHI PANTING ]
ARCHER: HOSHI, WHERE YOU GOING?
HOSHI: I DON'T THINK
YOU NEED A TRANSLATOR!
ARCHER: STAY HERE.
REED: THEIR BODIES
ARE BEING FLUSHED OUT
WITH SOME KIND OF FLUID.
ARCHER: ARE THEY ALL--
REED: ALL DEAD, SIR.
I'M AFRAID SO.
PHLOX: THEY'RE CLEAN.
T'POL: HOW MANY?
ARCHER: I DON'T KNOW.
ABOUT A DOZEN.
REED: 15.
ARCHER: THEY'RE BEING
DRAINED OF SOMETHING.
WHOEVER DID IT
WENT TO A LOT OF TROUBLE.
MY GUESS IS
THEY'RE COMING BACK.
T'POL: WE SHOULD LEAVE.
ARCHER: THERE ARE 15
DEAD PEOPLE OVER THERE.
WE CAN'T LEAVE.
T'POL: YOUR REASON
FOR BOARDING THAT VESSEL
WAS TO PROVIDE ASSISTANCE
IF ASSISTANCE WAS REQUIRED.
CLEARLY, IT NO LONGER IS.
YOU'RE TELLING ME THAT WE
SHOULD JUST LEAVE THEM THERE?
T'POL: WHAT'S THE ALTERNATIVE?
YOUR INTENTIONS WERE
ADMIRABLE, CAPTAIN,
BUT NOTHING CAN BE DONE
FOR THAT CREW NOW.
AND IF WE REMAIN HERE, YOUR CREW
COULD BE PUT IN JEOPARDY.
[ BEEP ]
ARCHER: ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
TRAVIS: MAYWEATHER HERE, SIR.
ARCHER: GO TO WARP 3.
RESUME COURSE.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
PHLOX: NOT LONG AFTER
I BECAME A PHYSICIAN,
THERE WAS AN EXPLOSION
ON A CARGO SHIP
ORBITING MY HOMEWORLD.
I WAS PART OF THE FIRST
MEDICAL TEAM TO ARRIVE.
THERE WERE 17 BODIES
ON THE BRIDGE ALONE.
I'D NEVER SEEN THAT MANY DEAD
PEOPLE IN ONE PLACE BEFORE.
VERY DISTURBING.
YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO BE ASHAMED OF.
I SCREAMED
LIKE A 12-YEAR-OLD.
[ PHLOX CHUCKLES ]
WE'RE ALL FRIGHTENED
BY UNFAMILIAR THINGS.
YOU SHOULD BE GRATEFUL
THAT YOUR BODY OF EXPERIENCE
DOESN'T INCLUDE
ROOMS FULL OF CORPSES.
HOSHI: NOBODY ELSE SCREAMED.
HAS SHE BEEN EATING?
PHLOX: NOT SO FAR.
SHE HAS BEEN UNDER
A GREAT DEAL OF STRESS,
BUT I'M HOPING THIS PROTEIN
CONCENTRATE WHETS HER APPETITE.
HOSHI: I'M A TRANSLATOR.
I DIDN'T COME OUT HERE
TO SEE CORPSES
HANGING ON HOOKS.
IT GOES WITHOUT SAYING
THAT YOU'RE GOING TO ENCOUNTER
THE UNEXPECTED.
NOT CORPSES ON HOOKS.
HAVE YOU EVER CONSIDERED
THAT YOU MIGHT BE HAPPIER
BACK AT THE UNIVERSITY,
TEACHING?
I DID IT FOR YEARS.
IT WAS QUITE REWARDING.
HOSHI: I'M AN EXOLINGUIST.
I GRADUATED SECOND IN MY CLASS.
I SPENT THREE YEARS
IN STARFLEET TRAINING.
I WAS JONATHAN ARCHER'S
FIRST CHOICE FOR THIS MISSION.
EVERY INHABITED WORLD WE COME TO
IS GOING TO BE FILLED
WITH LANGUAGE.
SOME WILL HAVE HUNDREDS OF THEM.
HE NEEDS ME HERE.
IF SHE DOESN'T TAKE
THESE NUTRIENTS,
I'M AFRAID SHE WON'T SURVIVE.
HOSHI: ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S WHAT SHE EATS?
PHLOX: IT'S CLOSE ENOUGH.
HOSHI: I SHOULDN'T HAVE
BROUGHT HER ONBOARD.
MAYBE I COULD ASK THE CAPTAIN
TO TRY TO FIND A PLANET
WITH AN ARGON-RICH ATMOSPHERE.
PHLOX: MIGHT BE EASIER
JUST TO FEED HER TO MY BAT.
[ HOSHI SIGHS ]
SHE NEEDS TO GET BACK
TO AN ENVIRONMENT
THAT IS MORE SUITED TO HER.
PHLOX: HMM. PERHAPS SOMEPLACE
WHERE SHE COULD TEACH.
TUCKER: WHAT KIND
OF PASTA IS THIS?
IT'S GREAT.
ARCHER: CHEF TOLD ME.
I DON'T REMEMBER.
TUCKER: TOO SPICY FOR YOU?
T'POL: IT'S FINE.
TUCKER: MALCOLM'S ANXIOUS
TO RUN ANOTHER WEAPONS TEST,
ESPECIALLY AFTER WHAT HAPPENED.
TEA?
T'POL: NO, THANK YOU.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: SURE, THANKS.
TUCKER: I HEARD
THEY WERE HUMANOID.
IS THAT RIGHT?
ARCHER: HUMANOID.
TUCKER: DID THEY LOOK
ANYTHING LIKE US?
ARCHER: THEY WERE IN UNIFORM.
TUCKER: BUT YOU DIDN'T
RECOGNIZE THE SPECIES?
THEY WERE CREWMEN,
MURDERED ON THEIR OWN SHIP.
15 DEAD CREWMEN.
I DETECTED A STELLAR NURSERY
ALONG OUR PRESENT COURSE.
TUCKER: I SAW ONE ONCE THROUGH
THE BIG LENS OUTSIDE ANCHORAGE.
A CLOSER VIEW MIGHT ALLEVIATE
SOME OF THE CREW'S TENSION.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
THE TENSION BOTHERING YOU?
NOT IN THE LEAST.
MUST BE GREAT
NOT TO LET THINGS BOTHER YOU.
NO REMORSE, NO GUILT.
WHAT IF THEY WERE VULCANS?
THINK YOU WOULD'VE REACTED
THE SAME WAY?
THEY WEREN'T VULCANS.
I SAID
WHAT IF THEY WERE VULCANS?
WOULD YOU HAVE JUST
LEFT THEM THERE
HANGING LIKE
SLAUGHTERED ANIMALS?
DON'T YOU THINK MAYBE
YOU WOULD'VE TAKEN THEM DOWN,
TRIED TO FIGURE OUT
WHO THEY WERE,
MADE SOME EFFORT
TO CONTACT THEIR FAMILIES?
WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE THEY CAME FROM.
IT WOULD BE VERY DIFFICULT
TO LOCATE THEIR FAMILIES.
WE DIDN'T EVEN TRY.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WHAT IF THEY WERE HUMANS?
WOULD YOU JUST STICK YOUR TAIL
BETWEEN YOUR LEGS AND RUN?
LEAVE THEM THERE TO ROT?
AM I THE ONLY ONE WHO'S HAVING
A PROBLEM WITH THIS?
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF, SIR.
WHOEVER KILLED THOSE PEOPLE
ARE PROBABLY COMING BACK.
SO WE SHOULD AVOID
CONFRONTATION AT ANY COST.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE SAYING?
IS THAT WHAT YOU VULCANS DO?
BURY YOUR HEADS IN THE SAND
AND THEN JUST FLY ON BY?
WE VULCANS WOULD HAVE NEVER
GONE ONBOARD THAT SHIP
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
[ LAUGHS ] OH.
YOU GOT AN ANSWER
FOR EVERYTHING, DON'T YOU?
WE HAVE A CODE OF BEHAVIOR,
AND WE TRY TO OBEY IT.
YOU MAY NOT BELIEVE THIS,
BUT HUMANS HAVE
A CODE OF BEHAVIOR, TOO.
IT TOOK A FEW THOUSAND YEARS,
BUT I THINK WE'RE STARTING
TO GET IT RIGHT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I ALMOST IGNORED IT.
WE'VE REVERSED COURSE, SIR.
WE SHOULD BE BACK AT
THE COORDINATES IN FIVE HOURS.
ARCHER: YOU DON'T HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH THE ENVIRONMENTAL SUIT?
PHLOX: NOT AT ALL.
ARCHER: GOOD.
I'M GOING TO NEED YOU
TO EXAMINE THE BODIES,
TRY TO IDENTIFY THEIR SPECIES.
AND, WHILE YOU'RE AT IT,
IT WOULDN'T HURT
IF YOU COULD FIGURE OUT
WHAT'S BEING DONE TO THEM.
PHLOX: I'LL SEE WHAT
I CAN DO, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: YOU WANTED TO SEE
WHAT'S GOING ON OVER THERE.
NOW'S YOUR CHANCE.
I CAN'T THINK OF A BETTER WAY
TO FIND THEIR PEOPLE
THAN THROUGH
THEIR OWN COM SYSTEM.
YOU'RE GOING TO NEED TO GET IT
UP AND RUNNING.
TUCKER: AYE, AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: HOSHI'LL DECIPHER THEIR
LANGUAGE AND COMPOSE A MESSAGE.
HOPEFULLY IT WILL MAKE SENSE.
HOSHI: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: I'M SORRY, ENSIGN.
REED: I'LL BRING
A SECURITY DETAIL.
ARCHER: THERE'S NO ONE
OVER THERE WHO CAN HURT US.
STAY HERE AND WORK
ON THOSE TARGETING SCANNERS.
PREPARE TO SUIT UP
AT...1400 HOURS.
DISMISSED.
ARCHER: HOW WERE THEY KILLED?
PHLOX: DIFFERENT WAYS.
THIS ONE WAS GIVEN
A LETHAL DOSE OF CHLORAXINE.
THE FIRST THREE BACK THERE
WERE SHOT--
PARTICLE WEAPONS, I BELIEVE.
THIS FELLOW HASN'T SUFFERED
AS MUCH CELLULAR DECAY.
HE'S OUR BEST CANDIDATE
FOR A POSTMORTEM.
CARE TO ASSIST?
[ BUZZING ]
[ WHIRRING ]
-[SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
-YEAH.
HOSHI: MAYBE IT'S A LOG.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
TUCKER: BEATS ME.
COULD BE A LAUNDRY LIST
OR INSTRUCTIONS ON HOW
TO CONQUER THE UNIVERSE.
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
THE GRAMMAR SOUNDS BIMODAL.
THEIR TRANSCEIVER'S INTACT.
LET'S HOPE THE NEXT TIME
WE MAKE FIRST CONTACT,
IT ISN'T WITH A ROOM
FULL OF CORPSES.
LET'S HOPE.
HOSHI: SHIP.
[ BUZZING ]
SHIP.
PHLOX: JUST WHAT I THOUGHT.
ARCHER: WHAT?
PHLOX: A ZYMUTH GLAND.
IT RELEASES TRIGLOBULIN
INTO THE BLOOD.
THAT'S WHAT ALL THESE
TUBES AND PUMPS ARE ABOUT.
WHOEVER DID THIS IS TRYING
TO COLLECT TRIGLOBULIN.
ARCHER: WHAT FOR?
PHLOX: OH, ANY NUMBER
OF REASONS.
TO CREATE MEDICINES, VACCINES.
SOME SPECIES
HAVE EVEN BEEN KNOWN
TO USE IT AS AN APHRODISIAC.
ARCHER: APHRODISIAC?
PHLOX: IT'S QUITE
A COMMON PRACTICE.
I'M SURPRISED YOU'RE
NOT FAMILIAR WITH IT.
HUMANS USED TO COLLECT
THE BILE OF BLACK BEARS,
GRIND DOWN RHINO HORNS,
THINGS LIKE THAT,
BUT NOT PEOPLE.
IT'S WORTH NOTING
THAT TRIGLOBULIN IS VERY SIMILAR
TO HUMAN LYMPHATIC FLUID.
HOSHI: HOW LONG BEFORE
THE TRANSCEIVER'S ONLINE?
TUCKER: A MINUTE OR TWO.
I CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF THIS--
AN ALIEN SPACESHIP,
SENDING OFF A MESSAGE
TO WHO KNOWS WHERE.
HOSHI: THE QUICKER
WE GET THIS DONE,
THE QUICKER WE CAN
GET BACK TO THE SHIP.
TUCKER: IT'S YOUR SECOND AWAY
MISSION IN TWO DAYS.
HOSHI: YEAH, GREAT.
TUCKER: I WISH I HAD
AN EAR FOR LANGUAGES.
THE CAPTAIN'S GONNA NEED
A TRANSLATOR WITH HIM
A LOT MORE OFTEN
THAN AN ENGINEER.
HOSHI: DISTRESS.
[ BUZZING ]
TWO OTHER TEACHERS AND I
ONCE TOOK A HYDRO-SKIMMER
OUT ONTO A SMALL TRIBUTARY
IN THE AMAZON,
YOU KNOW, TO SEE THE WILDLIFE--
SLOTHS, PINK DOLPHINS,
ALL KINDS OF SNAKES.
TUCKER: WOW.
HOSHI: IT GAVE ME THE CREEPS.
IF I DIDN'T LIKE
BEING AROUND ANACONDAS,
YOU CAN IMAGINE
HOW I FEEL ABOUT SULIBAN
OR WHOEVER BUTCHERED
THE CREW OF THIS SHIP.
I'M GONNA ASK THE CAPTAIN
TO TAKE ME HOME.
YOU SERIOUS?
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER LEFT
THE UNIVERSITY.
I'M NOT SUITED FOR THIS.
TUCKER: GIVE IT A TRY.
YOU'LL BE FINE.
HOSHI: YOU WEREN'T
HERE YESTERDAY.
I SAW THOSE BODIES
AND FELL APART.
THE CAPTAIN NEEDS
A TRANSLATOR HE CAN COUNT ON,
SOMEONE WHO SHOWS A LITTLE GRACE
UNDER PRESSURE.
THAT ISN'T ME.
YOU CAN'T BE SURE OF THAT.
OH, YES, I CAN.
DISTRESS.
[ BEEPING ]
[ SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
DISTRESS.
I THINK I'VE GOT IT.
SHIP IN DISTRESS.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ BEEPING ]
T'POL: T'POL TO ARCHER.
GO AHEAD.
T'POL: THERE'S A VESSEL
APPROACHING, CAPTAIN.
ITS POWER SIGNATURES
MATCH THE SCANS YOU TOOK
OF THOSE BIO-PUMPS.
IT APPEARS THAT WHOEVER
KILLED THAT CREW HAS RETURNED.
ARCHER: TIME TO GO, DOC.
ARCHER: TRIP, HOSHI,
DOCKING HATCH NOW.
DISTANCE--60,000 KILOMETERS.
T'POL: BRIDGE TO ARMORY.
REED: ARMORY.
WE HAVE A POTENTIALLY
HOSTILE VESSEL APPROACHING.
ARE YOU PREPARED
TO DEFEND THE SHIP?
THAT DEPENDS.
HOW LONG TILL IT GETS HERE?
TRAVIS: 10 MINUTES, MAYBE LESS.
THEN THE ANSWER
IS MOST LIKELY NO.
THE SCANNERS
ARE STILL OUT OF ALIGNMENT.
LOOK, IF YOU WANTED ME TO HIT
A STATIONARY DAIRY BARN,
THEN I COULD ACCOMMODATE YOU,
BUT NOT A MOVING VESSEL.
DO THE BEST YOU CAN,
BUT I NEED YOU ON THE BRIDGE
IN FIVE MINUTES.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO T'POL.
DEPLOY THE DOCKING ARM.
ARM EXTENDED.
ARCHER: HOW CLOSE ARE THEY?
8,000 KILOMETERS.
ARCHER: WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS?
OUR SENSORS
CAN'T PENETRATE THEIR SHIELDING.
HAVE YOU TRIED HAILING THEM?
T'POL: YES.
THERE'S BEEN NO RESPONSE.
TRY AGAIN.
THE POD'S ON THE ARM.
T'POL TO ARCHER.
THEY'RE STILL NOT RESPONDING.
REED: THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
THEY'RE TARGETING OUR ENGINES.
ARCHER: WE'RE ALMOST IN.
STAND BY TO JUMP TO WARP.
ARCHER: DOORS.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
IT DOESN'T FEEL LIKE
WE'VE GONE TO WARP.
T'POL: OUR PORT NACELLE
HAS BEEN DAMAGED.
ARCHER: HAVE MALCOLM
ARM THE TORPEDOES.
REPORT.
TRAVIS: WE'RE DEAD
IN THE WATER, SIR.
T'POL: THEY SEEM TO HAVE
STOPPED FIRING.
THEY'RE CLOSING
ON OUR POSITION.
ARCHER: MALCOLM?
REED: BOTH FORWARD TUBES
LOADED AND READY, SIR.
ARCHER: STAND BY STARBOARD TUBE.
REED: YES, SIR.
FIRE.
ARCHER: STAND BY PORT TUBE.
REED: READY.
FIRE.
ARCHER: TRIP,
WARP STATUS.
TUCKER: THE NACELLE'S BEEN
COMPLETELY DEPOLARIZED.
I'M AFRAID WE'RE
STUCK HERE FOR A WHILE.
[ BUZZING ]
[ HOSHI GASPS ]
TRAVIS: WHAT WAS THAT?
PHLOX: A SUBMOLECULAR BIO-SCAN.
YOU'VE BEEN PROBED, ENSIGN.
WE'VE ALL BEEN PROBED.
THEY HAVE NO DOUBT DISCOVERED
THAT YOUR LYMPHATIC SYSTEMS
CONTAIN SOME USEFUL COMPOUNDS.
ARCHER: GET TO THE ARMORY.
START DISTRIBUTING
HAND WEAPONS.
POST SECURITY TEAMS AT LEVEL--
[ BEEPING ]
TRAVIS: SIR, ANOTHER VESSEL
JUST DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE ON
AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
ARCHER: LET'S SEE IT.
[ BEEPING ]
HOSHI: THEY'RE HAILING US.
ARCHER: PUT IT UP.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
T'POL: CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: HE'S FROM THE SAME
SPECIES AS THE MURDERED CREW.
THEY MUST'VE PICKED UP
YOUR DISTRESS CALL.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
ARCHER: TELL HIM
THE SHIP ABOVE US
KILLED THE CREW
OF THE CARGO VESSEL.
THEY'RE ABOUT
TO DO THE SAME TO US.
[ BEEPING ]
I TOLD HIM WHAT YOU SAID, SIR,
BUT I DOUBT IT MADE ANY SENSE.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THIS ISN'T EXACTLY SPANISH
WE'RE DEALING WITH HERE.
I'D BE LUCKY IF I'M GETTING
HALF THE VOCABULARY RIGHT.
REED: THEY'VE LOCKED ON TO US
WITH SOME KIND OF
STABILIZING BEAM.
ARCHER: USE THE IMPULSE ENGINES.
GET US THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
TRAVIS: I CAN'T, SIR.
THEIR BEAM'S DISRUPTING
ALL OUR PROPULSION SYSTEMS.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
HOSHI: IT SEEMS HE GOT
THE PART ABOUT
KILLING THE CARGO-SHIP CREW,
BUT HE BELIEVES WE DID IT, SIR.
A-AT LEAST I THINK HE DOES.
T'POL: TELL HIM WE SENT
THE DISTRESS CALL.
WHY WOULD WE KILL HIS PEOPLE
AND THEN DO THAT?
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
I THINK I UNDERSTOOD THIS ONE.
HE SAYS THE DISTRESS CALL
CAME FROM HIS SHIP, NOT OURS.
WE NEEDED THEIR FREQUENCIES.
GOING THERE WAS
THE ONLY WAY TO FIND THEM.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
SOMETHING ABOUT DNA SCANS.
HE WANTS TO KNOW WHY WE
WERE THERE TWO YEARS AGO.
TWO YEARS AGO?
HE PROBABLY MEANS TWO DAYS, SIR.
THE PHONETIC PROCESSOR IS
STILL HAVING TROUBLE LOCKING ON.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
I'M NOT CERTAIN, BUT I DON'T
THINK HE'S GONNA HELP US.
REED: THEY'RE 50 METERS
ABOVE US.
49.
ARCHER: THE PUMPS.
TELL THEM TO RUN SCANS
ON THE BIO-PUMPS THAT ARE
HOOKED UP TO THE CORPSES.
THEY'LL SEE
THEY'RE NOT OUR TECHNOLOGY.
HAVE THEM COMPARE
THE POWER SIGNATURES
TO THE SHIP THAT'S ABOUT
TO LAND ON OUR ROOF.
WHERE ARE THEY, MALCOLM?
THEY'VE STOPPED
AT ABOUT 10 METERS.
HOSHI: I'M HAVING TROUBLE
WITH THE WORD "PUMPS," SIR.
I'VE GOT THE PROCESSOR
SEARCHING FOR SYNONYMS.
[ SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
THE TRANSLATOR'S NOT MAKING A
WHOLE LOT OF SENSE TO HIM, SIR.
HE'S GETTING FRUSTRATED.
I THINK HE'S RUNNING
OUT OF PATIENCE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: THEN FORGET
THE TRANSLATOR.
DO IT YOURSELF.
HOSHI: DO WHAT MYSELF?
ARCHER: TALK TO HIM.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE, SIR.
I-I-I HAVEN'T EVEN LEARNED
THEIR BASIC CONJUGATIONS.
TALK TO HIM, HOSHI.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE PERFECT.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND. I DON'T
EVEN KNOW HOW TO SAY "PUMP."
I'LL GET IT ALL WRONG.
IT'LL--IT'LL JUST
MAKE THINGS WORSE.
THINGS CAN'T GET MUCH WORSE.
SIR.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
REED: CAPTAIN, THEY'VE STARTED
DRILLING INTO THE HULL.
HOSHI, HOSHI.
I NEED YOU TO DO THIS.
WE ALL DO.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE.
[ CONVERSATION
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
ARCHER: AGAIN.
ARCHER: WHAT'D HE SAY?
ARCHER: ENSIGN.
[ BEEPING ]
REED: THEY'RE TARGETING
THE VESSEL ABOVE US.
TRAVIS: WE'VE GOT IMPULSE BACK.
ARCHER: MOVE US AWAY.
REED: CAPTAIN, I MAY BE WRONG,
BUT I THINK I'VE GOT
THE SCANNERS ALIGNED.
PERMISSION TO LAUNCH
A TORPEDO.
GRANTED.
ARCHER: NICE OF THEM TO WAIT
TILL WE GOT CLEAR.
ALL STOP.
I THINK WE MAY HAVE
JUST MADE A FRIEND...
THANKS TO YOU.
ARCHER:
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, MAY 6, 2151.
AFTER HELPING THEM RECOVER
THEIR DEAD CREWMEN,
WE HAD A CHANCE TO SPEND
SOME TIME WITH THE AXANAR.
TURNS OUT THEY'RE ANDROGYNOUS
AND LIVE OVER 400 YEARS.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO MEETING THEM AGAIN
UNDER BETTER CIRCUMSTANCES.
BEFORE WE RESUME OUR COURSE,
I'VE AGREED
TO MAKE A BRIEF DETOUR.
THIS ISN'T EXACTLY
LIKE THE PLACE YOU CAME FROM,
BUT IT'S CLOSE ENOUGH.
IT'S NOT THAT HARD TO ADAPT.
YOU'RE GONNA DO JUST FINE HERE.