[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
NOVAKOVICH:
HOW CAN YOU EAT THAT STUFF?
CUTLER:
IT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT.
NOVAKOVICH: HUH. AT LEAST
THIS TASTES LIKE SOMETHING.
CUTLER: I GUESS IT JUST TAKES
A MORE DISCRIMINATING PALATE
TO APPRECIATE VULCAN CUISINE.
NOVAKOVICH: [ LAUGHING ]
CUTLER: DID YOU KNOW THERE WERE
OVER 5,000 SUBSPECIES OF TERMITE
ON LORACUS PRIME?
NOVAKOVICH: HMM.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
NOVAKOVICH: I THOUGHT WE WERE
HEADED FOR A NEBULA.
CUTLER:
ANYBODY HEAR ABOUT THIS?
MAN: NOT A WORD.
CUTLER: I WONDER IF SOMEBODY
LIVES THERE.
NOVAKOVICH:
THERE'S A LOT OF PLANT LIFE.
IT MIGHT BE AN OXYGEN
ATMOSPHERE.
CUTLER: HMM. WHAT DO YOU THINK?
FIRST CONTACT?
MAN: I DON'T SEE ANY CITIES
OR AGRICULTURE.
NOVAKOVICH: MAYBE THEY LIVE
UNDERGROUND OR IN THE WATER.
CUTLER: IS THAT SNOW
ON THOSE MOUNTAINS?
NOVAKOVICH: YOU'D THINK
THE CAPTAIN WOULD MAKE
AN ANNOUNCEMENT OR SOMETHING.
CUTLER: WELL, CALL HIM.
ARCHER: T'POL?
T'POL: 17% OXYGEN, 81% NITROGEN.
TUCKER:
SOUNDS LIKE HOME.
ARCHER: ANY PEOPLE?
T'POL: THE PLANET SUPPORTS
A DIVERSE ECOLOGY, BUT THERE
ARE NO SIGNS OF HUMANOID LIFE.
ARCHER: STILL, SOMEONE
MAY HAVE A CLAIM ON IT.
WE DON'T WANT TO GO WALTZING
INTO THEIR BACK YARD.
SCAN FOR MARKER BUOYS, BEACONS,
MANMADE SATELLITES.
REED: NONE IN RANGE, SIR.
LOOKS LIKE NO ONE'S
PLANTED A FLAG JUST YET.
ARCHER:
PREP A SHUTTLEPOD, MR. TUCKER.
I LIKE THE LOOKS
OF THE NORTHERN CONTINENT.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND
A GOOD PLACE TO SET DOWN.
MAYWEATHER: YES, SIR.
T'POL: CAPTAIN,
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF PROTOCOLS
YOU MAY WANT TO CONSIDER.
ARCHER: PROTOCOLS.
T'POL: VULCAN SHIPS WOULD BEGIN
BY SENDING AUTOMATED PROBES DOWN
TO COLLECT MORE DETAILED SCANS.
IF THE PLANET PROVED
TO BE MINSHARA-CLASS,
WE WOULD THEN CONDUCT A
GEOPHYSICAL SURVEY FROM ORBIT.
MAYWEATHER: MINSHARA-CLASS?
SATO: SUITABLE
FOR HUMANOID LIFE.
ARCHER:
HOW LONG WOULD ALL THAT TAKE?
T'POL: SIX OR SEVEN DAYS.
TUCKER: YOU EXPECT US
TO SIT UP HERE FOR A WEEK
WHILE PROBES HAVE ALL THE FUN?
T'POL: THIS PLANET HAS BEEN HERE
A LONG TIME.
IT WILL STILL BE HERE
IN SEVEN DAYS.
ARCHER: I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
HAVE A MORE CAUTIOUS APPROACH,
BUT WE DIDN'T COME OUT HERE
TO TIPTOE AROUND.
GET THE POD READY.
I'D LIKE YOU TO PUT TOGETHER
THE SURVEY TEAM.
I ASSUME THAT'S NOT A VIOLATION
OF PROTOCOL.
RUSSELL WATSON:
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
MAN: THANKS.
CUTLER: I TRIED SOME PLOMEEK
BROTH THIS MORNING.
IT WAS VERY GOOD.
VULCAN FOOD IS...INTERESTING.
T'POL: DID YOU STERILIZE
THE SAMPLE CONTAINERS?
CUTLER: YES.
THANKS FOR CHOOSING ME
FOR THIS MISSION.
T'POL: YOU WERE SELECTED BECAUSE
YOUR SPECIALTY IS ENTOMOLOGY.
THIS PLANET HAS
A DIVERSE INSECT POPULATION.
CUTLER: RIGHT.
TUCKER: YOU'D HAVE BETTER LUCK
MAKING FRIENDS WITH A HOUSEFLY.
CUTLER: YEAH.
TUCKER: WOW.
CUTLER:
WORTH EVERY LIGHT-YEAR.
ARCHER: SET US DOWN JUST EAST
OF THOSE HILLS.
MAYWEATHER: AYE, SIR.
PORTHOS: [ BARKS ]
TUCKER:
WHERE NO DOG HAS GONE BEFORE.
ARCHER: [ LAUGHS ]
OH, I ALMOST FORGOT
WHAT FRESH AIR SMELLS LIKE.
T'POL: THE ATMOSPHERE
CONTAINS TRACE ELEMENTS
OF NITROGEN DIOXIDE,
CHLOROMETHANE --
ARCHER:
PUT THAT THING AWAY.
TAKE A MINUTE TO ENJOY YOURSELF.
THE SKY EVER GET
THIS BLUE ON VULCAN?
T'POL: OCCASIONALLY.
ARCHER: WE'RE WALKING
ON AN ALIEN WORLD,
LIGHT-YEARS FROM EARTH
OR VULCAN.
DOESN'T THAT IMPRESS YOU?
T'POL: I'VE BEEN TO 36
MINSHARA-CLASS PLANETS.
THIS EXPERIENCE IS ONLY
MARGINALLY DIFFERENT.
TUCKER: PERFECT.
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE.
ARCHER: SMILE.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
BE SURE TO GET A COPY OF THAT
TO THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND.
T'POL: YOU HAVE
YOUR ASSIGNMENTS.
WE'LL RENDEZVOUS
HERE AT 1900 HOURS...
UNLESS THE CAPTAIN WANTS US
TO POSE FOR MORE PICTURES.
[ SNIFFS ]
ARCHER: I'M AFRAID MY LOG ENTRY
ISN'T GONNA DO THIS JUSTICE.
TUCKER: A CABIN IN THESE WOODS
WOULD BE NICE.
ARCHER: THREE WEEKS
IN DEEP SPACE,
YOU'RE READY TO JUMP SHIP?
TUCKER: [ LAUGHS ] DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU GUYS'D BE LOST WITHOUT ME.
[ CHUCKLES ]
MAYWEATHER: IT'S BEAUTIFUL,
ALL RIGHT,
BUT I COULDN'T CALL A PLACE HOME
UNLESS IT CAME WITH A PAIR
OF WARP NACELLES.
TUCKER: BOOMERS.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER.
T'POL: IS THERE
A PROBLEM, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: NO, NO PROBLEM. WHY?
T'POL: WE WERE SCHEDULED TO
RENDEZVOUS 15 MINUTES AGO.
ARCHER: SORRY.
WE LOST TRACK OF TIME.
WE'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
T'POL: WE'VE IDENTIFIED SEVERAL
NOCTURNAL MARSUPIALS.
I'D LIKE TO KEEP CREWMEN
CUTLER AND NOVAKOVICH
WITH ME OVERNIGHT
TO STUDY THEM.
ARCHER: I'M GLAD TO SEE
YOU'RE GETTING
IN THE SPIRIT OF THINGS.
PICK YOU UP IN THE MORNING.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN, IF IT'S
ALL RIGHT WITH YOU,
TRAVIS AND I WOULD LIKE
TO STAY AS WELL.
MAYWEATHER: WE WOULD?
TUCKER: WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU SLEPT UNDER THE STARS?
THERE'S PLENTY OF CAMPING GEAR
IN THE POD.
T'POL: THIS ISN'T SHORE LEAVE.
THIS IS A RESEARCH MISSION.
ARCHER: WHY CAN'T IT BE
A LITTLE BIT OF BOTH?
RESEARCH ISN'T THE ONLY REASON
WE'RE OUT HERE.
PITCH YOUR TENT, COMMANDER.
TUCKER:
THANKS, CAPTAIN.
DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL KEEP OUT OF YOUR HAIR.
MAYWEATHER: KEEP IN MIND
THOSE CARGO VESSELS
WEREN'T EQUIPPED
FOR RESCUE OPERATIONS.
SO THE CAPTAIN WASN'T
SURE WHAT TO DO
WHEN HE PICKED UP
THE DISTRESS CALL.
BUT IT WASN'T A SHIP
THAT SENT THE SIGNAL.
IT WAS A LIFE POD
FROM ONE OF THE OLD
Y-500-CLASS FREIGHTERS.
TUCKER:
THOSE WERE RETIRED DECADES AGO.
MAYWEATHER: EXACTLY.
THE POD HAD BEEN DRIFTING
IN SPACE FOR 63 YEARS.
BIO-SCANS SHOWED ONE LIFE SIGN
INSIDE THE POD...
HUMAN.
THE ASSISTANT ENGINEER,
GEORGE WEBB, A FRIEND
OF MY UNCLE'S,
WAS ASSIGNED TO OPEN IT.
IT TOOK HIM OVER AN HOUR
TO CUT THROUGH THE HULL.
HE SAID THE METAL FELT STRANGE,
COLD TO THE TOUCH.
OF COURSE IT WAS COLD.
TUCKER: IT WAS FLOATING
IN SPACE FOR 60 YEARS.
MAYWEATHER: HE COULD
HEAR A TAPPING NOISE
COMING FROM INSIDE,
BUT WHEN HE FINALLY GOT IT OPEN,
THE POD WAS EMPTY.
NO BODY, NOTHING.
A FEW DAYS LATER,
WEBB STARTED ACTING STRANGE --
GETTING INTO FIGHTS
WITH THE CREW,
MUTTERING TO HIMSELF
IN SOME SORT OF ALIEN LANGUAGE.
THEN ONE DAY, HE LOCKED HIMSELF
IN ENGINEERING
AND OVERLOADED
THE IMPULSE REACTORS.
HE ALMOST DESTROYED THE SHIP.
THEN HE SEALED HIMSELF
IN A LIFE POD AND EJECTED IT.
CUTLER: I ASSUME THE CAPTAIN
WENT AFTER HIM.
MAYWEATHER: THE REACTORS
WERE TOO BADLY DAMAGED.
SOME PEOPLE SAY
IT WAS AN ALIEN LIFE-FORM
THAT GOT INTO HIM.
OTHERS THINK IT WAS
THE GHOST OF A DEAD CREWMAN.
I NEVER KNEW WHAT TO BELIEVE.
BUT WEBB IS STILL OUT THERE,
DRIFTING.
WHEN THE SUBSPACE NOISE
IS REAL LOW,
SOME COM OFFICERS SAY
THEY CAN STILL HEAR THE ECHO
OF HIS DISTRESS CALL.
BEEP.
TUCKER: OOH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
T'POL: IT'S HIGHLY DOUBTFUL
THAT A DISTRESS BEACON
COULD FUNCTION CONTINUOUSLY
FOR 63 YEARS.
TUCKER: [ CHUCKLING ]
LET ME GUESS.
NO GHOST STORIES ON VULCAN.
CUTLER: THAT'S IT.
TO THE LEFT OF
THAT TRINARY CLUSTER.
TUCKER: WHAT?
CUTLER: OUR SUN.
MAYWEATHER: ARE YOU SURE?
CUTLER: YEAH, POSITIVE.
JUST ANOTHER SPECK OF LIGHT,
NO DIFFERENT THAN ANY OTHER.
TUCKER: WHEN I WAS A KID,
I'D GO CAMPING WITH MY BUDDIES.
WE'D SPEND HALF THE NIGHT
LOOKING UP AT THE STARS,
WONDERING WHAT OUR OWN SUN WOULD
LOOK LIKE FROM THIS FAR AWAY.
MAYWEATHER: NOW YOU KNOW.
NOVAKOVICH: [ GROANS ]
CUTLER: ARE YOU OKAY?
NOVAKOVICH: HEADACHE.
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT WITH YOU,
I'D LIKE TO LIE DOWN
FOR A WHILE
BEFORE WE GET BACK TO WORK?
T'POL: CERTAINLY.
TUCKER: HAS ANYONE HEARD THE ONE
ABOUT THE HAUNTED COMET?
[ LAUGHTER ]
CUTLER: WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU NOTICE SOMETHING?
THE FIREFLIES ARE GONE.
TUCKER: NICE GOING, TRAVIS.
YOU SCARED OFF THE BUGS.
MAYWEATHER: [ LAUGHING ]
CUTLER: MAYBE IT'S THE GHOST
OF GEORGE WEBB.
[ WIND GUSTING ]
TUCKER: LOOKS LIKE WE MIGHT HAVE
OURSELVES A LITTLE WEATHER!
T'POL: A FRONT IS APPROACHING
FROM THE SOUTHWEST.
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
MAYWEATHER:
IT MUST BE GUSTING AT 80 KPH.
TUCKER: THAT'S NOTHING
COMPARED TO A HURRICANE
COMING UP THROUGH
THE FLORIDA KEYS.
MAYWEATHER: TRY FLYING THROUGH
AN ION STORM AT WARP 2.
NOVAKOVICH:
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
CUTLER: WHAT?
NOVAKOVICH:
SOMEONE'S OUT THERE.
CUTLER: IT'S THE WIND.
TUCKER: AAH! SON OF A BITCH!
MAYWEATHER: WHAT IS IT?
TUCKER:
THERE'S SOMETHING IN MY BAG!
GIVE ME YOUR BOOT!
MAYWEATHER: WHAT FOR?
TUCKER: SO I CAN SQUASH IT!
MAYWEATHER: ARE WE ALLOWED
TO SQUASH ALIEN LIFE-FORMS?
TUCKER: IF THEY'RE INSIDE
YOUR SLEEPING BAG!
MAYWEATHER: BUT IT'S NOT INSIDE
THE SLEEPING BAG ANYMORE!
TUCKER: THERE IT IS!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHERE'D YOU PUT
THE PHASE PISTOLS?
MAYWEATHER:
YOU WANT TO SHOOT A BUG?
TUCKER: I'M JUST GONNA STUN IT.
T'POL: T'POL TO TUCKER.
TUCKER: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: IS THERE
A PROBLEM, COMMANDER?
TUCKER: OH, NO,
JUST AN EIGHT-INCH SCORPION
THING INSIDE OUR TENT.
T'POL: DO YOU REQUIRE
ASSISTANCE?
TUCKER: I THINK I'VE GOT IT
UNDER CONTROL.
NO, NOT THERE, IT'S OVER THERE!
T'POL, YOU SAID YOU FOUND
A CAVE THIS AFTERNOON?
T'POL: LESS THAN HALF
A KILOMETER FROM HERE.
TUCKER:
I THINK WE'RE GONNA NEED IT.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
ARCHER: COME IN.
NICE CATCH.
YOU'D MAKE A GOOD TWO-METER MAN.
TOO BAD WE DON'T HAVE
A POOL ONBOARD.
REED: A SHAME.
A WIND STORM'S MOVING ACROSS
THE NORTHERN CONTINENT.
LOOKS LIKE A NASTY ONE.
ARCHER: SURVEY TEAM?
REED: THEY'VE TAKEN SHELTER,
BUT I'D RECOMMEND
PULLING THEM OUT.
I'VE GOT A SHUTTLEPOD
ON STANDBY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'POL: YES, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
T'POL: WE'VE RELOCATED
INTO A CAVERN.
ARCHER: MR. REED THINKS
WE SHOULD COME DOWN AND GET YOU.
T'POL: A LANDING UNDER THESE
CONDITIONS MIGHT BE DIFFICULT.
WE'LL BE PROTECTED
UNTIL THE WINDS DIMINISH.
ARCHER:
WE'LL KEEP AN EYE ON THE STORM.
LET US KNOW
IF YOU NEED ANYTHING.
T'POL: UNDERSTOOD.
KEEP THE POD ON STANDBY,
JUST IN CASE.
REED: AYE, SIR.
TUCKER:
WHO'S GOT THE FOOD PACKS?
CUTLER: UH, NOPE.
TUCKER: TRAVIS?
MAYWEATHER: NOT ME, SIR.
T'POL: WE MUST'VE LEFT THEM
AT THE CAMPSITE.
MAYWEATHER: I'LL GO.
TUCKER: BE CAREFUL.
MAYWEATHER: [ GRUNTS ]
TRIP?!
HELLO?!
WAS ANYBODY OUTSIDE JUST NOW?
TUCKER: JUST YOU. WHY?
MAYWEATHER: THERE'S SOMEONE ELSE
OUT THERE.
CUTLER: WHAT?
MAYWEATHER: NEAR THE CAMPSITE.
TUCKER: I THINK WE'VE HAD ENOUGH
GHOST STORIES FOR ONE NIGHT.
MAYWEATHER: IT'S NO STORY.
T'POL: WE'VE SCANNED THE PLANET.
IT'S UNINHABITED.
MAYWEATHER: I'M TELLING YOU --
I SAW THREE PEOPLE.
CUTLER: THREE?
WHAT DID THEY LOOK LIKE?
MAYWEATHER: IT WAS TOO DARK.
TUCKER: SUBCOMMANDER?
T'POL:
OTHER THAN OURSELVES,
THERE ARE NO HUMANOID
LIFE-FORMS HERE.
MAYWEATHER: THERE COULD
BE SOMETHING WRONG
WITH YOUR SCANNER.
T'POL: IT'S FUNCTIONING
PERFECTLY.
PERHAPS YOU IMAGINED
SEEING THEM.
MAYWEATHER: THEY LOOKED
PRETTY REAL TO ME.
CUTLER: ETHAN?
NOVAKOVICH: THERE'S SOMEONE
BACK THERE. I HEARD VOICES.
ARE YOU GONNA TELL ME
I'M IMAGINING THINGS, TOO?
IT'S NOT SAFE HERE.
TUCKER: WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
THEY COULD BE FRIENDLY.
NOVAKOVICH: THEN WHY
ARE THEY HIDING?
WHY DON'T THEY COME OUT
AND SAY HELLO?
WE SHOULD LEAVE!
T'POL: WHERE DO YOU
PROPOSE WE GO?
BACK OUT INTO THE STORM?
NOVAKOVICH: IT'S BETTER
THAN BEING TRAPPED IN HERE.
TUCKER: SLOW DOWN, CREWMAN.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
MAYWEATHER: ETHAN!
TUCKER: STAY HERE.
TRAVIS.
T'POL: I'LL BE BACK SHORTLY.
CUTLER: WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
T'POL: IF THERE'S SOMEONE BACK
THERE, I INTEND TO FIND THEM.
MAYWEATHER: ETHAN!
[ GROWLING ]
TUCKER: TRAVIS!
I SAW ONE!
IT CAME RIGHT OUT OF THAT ROCK
LIKE IT WAS A PART OF IT.
MAYWEATHER:
THAT COULD EXPLAIN WHY
THEY'RE NOT SHOWING
UP ON OUR SCANNERS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
WHOA! OH!
TUCKER: IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
WE SHOULD GO BACK.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
CUTLER: WHO WERE THEY?
T'POL: EXCUSE ME?
CUTLER: WELL, WHO
WERE YOU TALKING TO?
T'POL: TALKING TO?
THERE'S NO ONE HERE.
TUCKER: WE'VE LOST NOVAKOVICH,
AND WE'RE APPARENTLY NOT ALONE.
THERE'S SOME KIND
OF LIFE-FORM DOWN HERE.
ARCHER: CAN YOU MAKE IT BACK
TO THE CAVERN?
TUCKER:
WE'RE HEADING THERE NOW, SIR.
MAYWEATHER: THE CAPTAIN'S
ON HIS WAY.
WE'RE GETTING OUT OF HERE.
TUCKER:
NOT A MOMENT TOO SOON.
FROM WHAT I SAW, THESE THINGS
LIVE INSIDE THE ROCK.
T'POL: I PERFORMED
A GEOLOGICAL ANALYSIS.
THE ROCKS ARE COMPOSED OF
LIMESTONE AND CORMALITE,
NOTHING MORE.
CUTLER:
SHE'S LYING, COMMANDER.
I SAW HER TALKING TO THEM.
TUCKER: CREWMAN?
CUTLER: IN THERE.
THERE WERE TWO OF THEM.
T'POL: SHE'S MISTAKEN.
CUTLER: NO, I'M NOT.
WHY WON'T YOU
TELL US WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT DO THEY WANT?
REED: I'VE GOT A FIX.
20 KILOMETERS NORTHEAST.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER TO NOVAKOVICH.
ETHAN. RESPOND.
NOVAKOVICH: WHO'S THERE?!
WHO IS THAT?!
ARCHER: THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
WE'RE ATTEMPTING TO LAND.
I WANT YOU
TO GET BACK TO THE CAVERN.
NOVAKOVICH: GO TO HELL!
T'POL: I HAVE NO REASON
TO DECEIVE YOU.
TUCKER: NEITHER DOES SHE.
YOU KEEP CLAIMING THESE
CREATURES DON'T EXIST,
BUT THE REST OF US
HAVE ALL SEEN THEM.
THAT'S A LITTLE STRANGE,
DON'T YOU THINK?
T'POL: I CAN'T EXPLAIN
WHAT YOU'VE SEEN,
BUT I ASSURE YOU
I DIDN'T SPEAK TO ANYONE.
TUCKER: I'D LIKE TO BELIEVE YOU,
BUT YOU VULCANS
DON'T EXACTLY HAVE
A SPOTLESS TRACK RECORD
WHEN IT COMES
TO BEING HONEST WITH US.
T'POL: YOUR POINT?
TUCKER: YOU'VE HELD THINGS
BACK BEFORE.
YOU MIGHT BE DOING IT AGAIN.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
TUCKER HERE.
ARCHER: WE'RE CLOSING IN
ON YOUR POSITION, TRIP.
THERE'S A CLEARING A HUNDRED
METERS FROM THE CAVE ENTRANCE.
GET TO IT.
REED: I'M READING THEM.
TWO KILOMETERS DUE WEST.
ARCHER: I'M TAKING US DOWN.
THERE'S A LOT OF WIND SHEAR
NEAR THE SURFACE.
ACTIVATE THE AUXILIARY
LANDING THRUSTERS.
ALTITUDE -- 70 METERS.
40 METERS.
I'LL HAVE TO TRY
A DIFFERENT VECTOR.
REED: STARBOARD!
ARCHER: I SEE IT.
REED: THRUSTER FOUR'S DOWN.
WE'RE LEAKING PLASMA COOLANT.
ARCHER: ALMOST THERE.
REED: SIR, WE CAN'T SAFELY
LAND IN THIS WIND
WITH A THRUSTER OUT.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
ARCHER: [ SIGHS ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO TUCKER.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN, AREN'T YOU
FORGETTING SOMETHING?
ARCHER: WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO WAIT
TILL THE WIND DIES DOWN.
TRY TO MANAGE TILL THEN.
TUCKER:
WE'LL DO OUR BEST, SIR.
ARCHER: IF YOU RUN ACROSS
ANY MORE OF THESE ALIENS,
TRY TO MAKE CONTACT.
SEE WHAT YOU
CAN FIND OUT ABOUT THEM.
TUCKER: UNDERSTOOD!
CUTLER: UGH. [ PANTING ]
MAYWEATHER: YOU OKAY?
CUTLER: [ CHUCKLES ]
NEVER BETTER.
TUCKER:
YOU HEARD THE CAPTAIN.
HE WANTS TO KNOW
ABOUT YOUR FRIENDS.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA TELL HIM?
T'POL: THIS IS POINTLESS.
TUCKER: IS IT?
WE'RE STUCK DOWN HERE
FOR GOD KNOWS HOW LONG
WITH A BUNCH OF ROCK PEOPLE
WHO, FOR ALL WE KNOW,
ARE STARING AT US
FROM THESE WALLS RIGHT NOW,
NOT TO MENTION
A CREWMAN OUT THERE
WHO PROBABLY
WON'T LAST THE NIGHT.
NOW, IF WE'RE GONNA
GET THROUGH THIS,
I NEED TO KNOW
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON.
YOU BEGINNING TO SEE MY POINT?
T'POL: I SHARE YOUR CONCERN
FOR CREWMAN NOVAKOVICH,
BUT AS I TOLD YOU --
TUCKER: YOU COULDN'T
CARE LESS ABOUT HIM
OR ANY OF THE REST OF US!
THAT'D REQUIRE SOME OF THOSE
USELESS HUMAN EMOTIONS.
T'POL: YOUR EMOTIONS
ARE BEGINNING
TO AFFECT YOUR JUDGMENT.
YOU'RE BECOMING IRRATIONAL.
TUCKER:
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN ME IRRATIONAL.
MAYWEATHER: SIR, I HATE TO ADD
TO OUR PROBLEMS,
BUT WE'RE RUNNING
LOW ON WATER.
TUCKER: GREAT.
WE'LL HAVE TO CONSERVE
WHAT'S LEFT.
T'POL: THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY.
I DETECTED WATER ABOUT
60 METERS IN THAT DIRECTION.
TUCKER:
HOW DO WE KNOW YOU'RE NOT
GOING IN THERE
TO TALK TO YOUR FRIENDS?
T'POL: JOIN ME IF YOU'D LIKE.
CUTLER: IT COULD BE A TRAP,
COMMANDER.
T'POL: I CAN SURVIVE WITHOUT
WATER FOR SEVERAL DAYS.
CAN YOU?
TUCKER: SIT DOWN.
YOU HEARD ME.
ARCHER: HOW'S HE DOING?
SATO: NOT GOOD.
HIS BIO-SIGNS ARE VERY ERRATIC.
ARCHER: TRY HIM AGAIN.
HOCHI: ENTERPRISE TO NOVAKOVICH.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
ETHAN?
NOVAKOVICH: [SCREAMING]
ARCHER: MR. REED,
CAN YOU GET A LOCK ON HIM?
REED: YES, SIR.
ARCHER:
LOOKS LIKE OUR ONLY CHOICE.
REED: UNDERSTOOD. STAND BY.
THERE'S A PROBLEM, SIR.
THERE ARE CONTAMINANTS
IN THE MATTER STREAM.
THE PHASE DISCRIMINATOR CAN'T
SEEM TO ISOLATE THE DEBRIS.
NOVAKOVICH: [ GROANS ]
REED: REED TO SICK BAY.
MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
TUCKER:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
T'POL: WORKING.
TUCKER: ON WHAT?
T'POL: SCANS I TOOK
THIS AFTERNOON.
TUCKER: FIND ANYTHING YOU WANT
TO TELL ME ABOUT?
T'POL: THERE'S NOTHING
OF SCIENTIFIC INTEREST
ON THIS PLANET.
OUR MISSION HERE
WAS A WASTE OF TIME.
TUCKER: THAT'S WHAT
YOU'D LIKE US TO THINK.
LET ME SEE THAT THING.
T'POL: THE READINGS
ARE IN VULCAN.
YOU WON'T UNDERSTAND.
TUCKER: NO, BUT HOSHI WOULD.
THIS COULD BE EVIDENCE.
T'POL: OF WHAT?
TUCKER: YOUR LITTLE CONSPIRACY.
T'POL: I WAS WRONG. THERE
IS SOMETHING OF INTEREST HERE.
I'VE LEARNED A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT HUMAN BEHAVIOR.
TUCKER: OH?
T'POL: UNDER STRESS,
YOU BECOME VOLATILE.
YOU'RE A FAR MORE
DANGEROUS SPECIES
THAN I PREVIOUSLY BELIEVED.
TUCKER: YOUR PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
TELLING US THAT KIND OF CRAP
FOR A HUNDRED YEARS!
LOOKS LIKE YOU FINALLY FOUND
A WAY TO PUT US
BACK IN OUR CAGE.
MAYWEATHER: SIR?
TUCKER: IMAGINE THE NEWS
BACK HOME, TRAVIS!
ENTERPRISE CREW FOUND DEAD!
SIX WEEKS INTO
THEIR HISTORIC VOYAGE,
THE BODIES OF
ALL 82 CREW MEMBERS
WERE LOCATED
ON AN UNINHABITED WORLD.
A VULCAN SHIP MADE
THE UNFORTUNATE DISCOVERY.
CAUSE OF DEATH
REMAINS A MYSTERY.
BUT WHAT VULCANS WON'T SAY
IS THEY KNOW EXACTLY
WHO ATTACKED US!
IN FACT, THEY ARRANGED
THE WHOLE THING!
THEY LURED US DOWN HERE SO THEY
COULD SABOTAGE OUR MISSION!
MAYWEATHER: YOU WERE THE ONE
WHO FOUND THESE CAVES,
AND IT WAS YOUR IDEA
TO STAY OVERNIGHT.
T'POL: I DIDN'T ASK
YOU OR MR. TUCKER TO JOIN US.
TUCKER:
WE KNOW YOU'RE HERE!
WHY DON'T YOU SHOW YOURSELVES?
YOU'RE NOT AFRAID
OF US, ARE YOU?
T'POL: THERE'S NO ONE THERE,
COMMANDER.
TUCKER: MAYBE YOU'RE WAITING
FOR THE OTHERS TO COME DOWN,
SO YOU CAN KILL US ALL AT ONCE!
DID YOU SEE THAT?!
T'POL: ALL I SEE
IS A DELUSIONAL ENGINEER!
TUCKER:
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE GETTING
A LITTLE VOLATILE
YOURSELF, SUBCOMMANDER.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD YOUR EMOTIONS
ALL LOCKED UP.
HAVING A LITTLE PROBLEM,
ARE YOU?
MAYWEATHER: COMMANDER, THERE!
YOU THINK WE'RE GONNA
WAIT AROUND HERE FOR
YOU TO SLAUGHTER US?
I'LL BLOW THIS WHOLE CAVE APART
IF I HAVE TO!
I KNOW YOU HEAR ME!
PHLOX: HUMAN SKIN
IS A RESILIENT ORGAN.
THESE WOUNDS
SHOULD HEAL NICELY.
ARCHER: CAN I TALK TO HIM?
PHLOX: YES, BUT I DOUBT
HE'LL MAKE MUCH SENSE.
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD
OF TROPOLISINE?
ARCHER: NO.
PHLOX: MM.
IT'S A PSYCHOTROPIC COMPOUND
KNOWN FOR ITS
HALLUCINOGENIC EFFECTS.
THIS CREWMAN'S BLOODSTREAM
IS FILLED WITH IT.
ARCHER: IF IT WAS DOWN
ON THE PLANET,
WHY DIDN'T OUR SENSORS
PICK IT UP?
PHLOX: NORMALLY IT'S FOUND
IN CERTAIN FLOWERING PLANTS.
PERHAPS YOUR SENSORS WEREN'T
CALIBRATED TO DETECT IT.
REED: OR PERHAPS IT WASN'T THERE
UNTIL THAT DAMN WIND STARTED.
ARCHER: HOW LONG WILL
THE EFFECTS LAST?
PHLOX: NOW THAT HE'S BACK
ON ENTERPRISE,
HE SHOULD BE ALL RIGHT
IN THREE OR FOUR HOURS.
ARCHER: WILL THIS TRO--
PHLOX: TROPOLISINE.
ARCHER: WILL IT AFFECT
T'POL AS WELL?
PHLOX:
THERE'S NO WAY TO KNOW.
IT MIGHT AFFECT HER
TO A LESSER DEGREE
OR A GREATER DEGREE.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'POL: YES, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: WE HAVE NOVAKOVICH.
T'POL: AND I HAVE A PHASE PISTOL
POINTED AT MY HEAD.
ARCHER: WHAT?
TUCKER: MY SUSPICIONS WERE
RIGHT ON THE NOSE, CAPTAIN.
OUR LITTLE VULCAN HERE
IS NOT WHAT SHE APPEARS TO BE --
NEVER WAS.
ARCHER: WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
TUCKER: THERE'S SOME KIND
OF CREATURES DOWN HERE.
THEY HIDE INSIDE SOLID ROCK.
TRAVIS AND I
HAVE BOTH SEEN THEM.
CUTLER SAW TWO OF THEM
TALKING TO T'POL.
THEY'RE UP TO SOMETHING,
BUT OF COURSE, SHE DENIES IT.
ARCHER: LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'VE ALL BEEN EXPOSED
TO A PSYCHOTROPIC COMPOUND.
IT CAUSES HEIGHTENED ANXIETY,
HALLUCINATIONS.
TUCKER: ARE YOU TELLING ME
THOSE CREATURES AREN'T REAL?
ARCHER: THE COMPOUND COMES
FROM THE POLLEN OF A FLOWER.
WE THINK IT WAS BLOWN DOWN
FROM THE MOUNTAINS
WHEN THE WINDS STARTED.
THE DOCTOR'S RUN TESTS
ON NOVAKOVICH.
HE THINKS HE'S GONNA
BE OKAY IN A FEW HOURS.
SO IF YOU CAN GET AS DEEP
AS YOU CAN INTO THE CAVES,
YOUR SYMPTOMS SHOULD DISSIPATE
AROUND THE SAME TIME.
TUCKER:
WE DIDN'T IMAGINE THIS, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER:
YOU DEALT WITH SIMULATIONS
VERY CLOSE TO THIS
IN STARFLEET TRAINING.
YOU'RE FAMILIAR
WITH MIND-ALTERING AGENTS.
WE'LL BE DOWN TO GET YOU
AS SOON AS THE WINDS LET UP.
TUCKER:
YOU'RE NOT HERE, CAPTAIN.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S GOING ON.
ARCHER: PUT YOUR WEAPON DOWN,
TRIP. THAT'S AN ORDER.
T'POL?
T'POL: HE'S LOWERED
HIS PHASE PISTOL, SIR.
ARCHER:
HAVE YOU BEEN AFFECTED?
T'POL: YES, BUT ONLY SLIGHTLY.
ARCHER:
TRY TO HOLD ON. ARCHER OUT.
GET TO THE BRIDGE.
I WANT A WEATHER REPORT.
TUCKER: TRAVIS.
YOU STILL WITH ME?
I NEED YOU ON YOUR FEET.
THOSE THINGS COULD COME BACK
AT ANY TIME.
LISTEN TO ME.
I'M GIVING YOU AN ORDER.
WHAT'S WRONG?
ENSIGN?
WHAT'D YOU DO TO HIM?
I CAN SEE WHY YOU GET ALONG
SO WELL WITH THEM.
SNEAKING AROUND
IN THE SHADOWS --
THAT'S SECOND NATURE
TO YOU VULCANS, ISN'T IT?
T'POL: [ SPEAKS VULCAN ]
TUCKER: I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU JUST SAID,
BUT IT DIDN'T SOUND VERY NICE.
YOU'RE MAKING A MISTAKE
WORKING WITH HER.
SHE'LL STAB YOU IN THE BACK
FIRST CHANCE SHE GETS.
TELL YOU WHAT.
COME OUT, AND WE'LL SETTLE THIS
PEACEFULLY.
WHATEVER SHE TOLD YOU
ABOUT HUMANS --
IT'S NOT TRUE.
YOU CAN SEE FOR YOURSELF.
SAY SOMETHING!
[ PANTING ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YES, SIR.
I KNOW, I KNOW,
BUT THEY'RE NOT
GIVING ME MUCH CHOICE.
I GOT TO PROTECT MY CREW.
I UNDERSTAND, MR. VELIK,
BUT I CAN'T DO THAT.
THEY'RE TRYING TO KILL US.
NICE TRY.
T'POL: [ SPEAKS VULCAN ]
REED: THE CENTER OF THE STORM
HAS ALREADY PASSED OVER THEM,
BUT THE SYSTEM SPANS
SOME 500 KILOMETERS.
WE WON'T BE ABLE TO LAND
A SHUTTLEPOD BEFORE DAWN.
ARCHER: WHEN'S THAT?
REED: NINE HOURS.
PHLOX:
PHLOX TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
PHLOX: PLEASE REPORT TO SICK BAY
IMMEDIATELY. IT'S URGENT.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT YOU SAID
HE WAS GONNA BE FINE.
PHLOX: I DID.
BUT EACH TROPOLISINE ATOM
CONTAINS A STRAY NEUTRON.
WHEN IT STARTED TO BREAK DOWN
IN HIS BLOODSTREAM,
IT RELEASED
AN UNDETECTABLE TOXIN.
I'VE INJECTED HIM
WITH INAPROVALINE,
BUT I...THINK
IT MAY BE TOO LATE.
IF I'D RUN A SUBMOLECULAR SCAN,
I MIGHT HAVE ANTICIPATED
THE COMPLICATION,
BUT THERE WAS NO REASON TO.
AT LEAST,
THERE DIDN'T SEEM TO BE.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW SORRY I AM, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER:
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?
PHLOX: THEY SPENT LESS TIME
EXPOSED TO THE POLLEN.
ARCHER: I'VE GOT FOUR PEOPLE
DOWN ON THE SURFACE, DOCTOR!
I NEED TO KNOW
IF THEY'RE GONNA BE DEAD
WHEN WE GET THERE
IN THE MORNING.
TUCKER: STAY AWAKE, TRAVIS.
CAN'T AFFORD TO HAVE
YOU GOING OUT ON ME!
MAYWEATHER: I'M...TRYING, SIR.
TRUCKER: CUTLER, YOU OKAY?
CUTLER: [ GROANS ]
TUCKER: IF YOU'RE WAITING
FOR ME TO PASS OUT,
YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
HAVE YOUR FRIENDS
COME OUT NOW AND DO WHATEVER
THEY'RE GONNA DO.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
T'POL: T'POL.
ARCHER: HOW ARE YOU DOING?
TUCKER: WHO'S THAT?
ARCHER: IT'S THE CAPTAIN, TRIP.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
T'POL: HE'S IRRATIONAL, SIR.
MAYWEATHER AND CUTLER
ARE NEARLY UNCONSCIOUS.
ARCHER: BOTH OF YOU LISTEN
TO ME VERY CAREFULLY.
NOVAKOVICH MAY BE DYING.
TURNS OUT THE POLLEN
CONTAINS SOME KIND OF TOXIN
OUR SENSORS HADN'T DETECTED.
HE'S RESPONDING TO MEDICATION,
BUT HIS ODDS OF RECOVERY WOULD
BE A HELL OF A LOT BETTER
IF WE'D TREATED HIM SOONER.
THE DOCTOR AND MALCOLM
ARE SYNTHESIZING AMPOULES
OF INAPROVALINE.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO USE THE
TRANSPORTER TO GET IT TO YOU,
BUT IT'S IMPERATIVE
THAT YOU INOCULATE YOURSELVES
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M SAYING?
TUCKER: TAKING AN INJECTION
ISN'T GONNA CHANGE A DAMN THING!
DON'T YOU SEE THAT?
THEY'RE PLANNING
SOMETHING, CAPTAIN --
FIRST US, THEN ALL OF YOU!
[ CONVERSATION IN VULCAN ]
ARCHER:
WHAT'S GOING ON, HOSHI?
SATO: SHE SAYS TRIP
IS GONNA KILL HER,
AND I DON'T THINK
SHE'S IMAGINING IT.
TUCKER: SAY ONE MORE WORD OF
THAT GIBBERISH, AND I'M GONNA
SPLIT YOU IN TWO!
ARCHER: TRIP, LISTEN TO ME.
THE POLLEN'S AFFECTING HER, TOO.
THINK ABOUT IT.
YOU'VE HEARD OF PEOPLE
SUFFERING FROM DEMENTIA
WHO REVERT
TO THEIR NATIVE LANGUAGE.
SHE CAN'T HELP IT.
TUCKER: THE ONLY THING
THAT'S AFFECTING HER
ARE THOSE ROCK PEOPLE.
IF I CAN STOP HER NOW,
I CAN SAVE ENTERPRISE.
ARCHER: TRIP, HOW LONG
HAVE WE KNOWN EACH OTHER?
TUCKER: WHAT'S THAT GOT TO DO
WITH ANYTHING?
ARCHER: REMEMBER WHEN YOUR
E.V. PACK FROZE UP ON TITAN
DURING THE OMEGA
TRAINING MISSION?
YOU GOT NITROGEN NARCOSIS.
YOU STARTED TO TRY
TO TAKE OFF YOUR HELMET.
YOU REMEMBER
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT?
TUCKER: WHAT'S YOUR POINT?!
ARCHER: I ORDERED YOU
TO KEEP YOUR HELMET ON.
YOU WERE DELIRIOUS,
THOUGHT YOU WERE GONNA DIE,
BUT YOU OBEYED THAT ORDER
BECAUSE YOU TRUSTED ME.
I'M ASKING YOU TO TRUST ME NOW.
TAKE THE INJECTION.
THEN WE'LL DEAL
WITH THESE ROCK PEOPLE.
TUCKER: TOO LATE, CAPTAIN!
I'M NOT GONNA DIE
WITH A HYPOSPRAY IN MY HAND.
ARCHER: TRIP.
TUCKER: NO!
IT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN!
ARCHER: ALL RIGHT.
FORGET THE MEDICINE.
I THINK IT'S TIME I EXPLAIN
WHAT'S REALLY GOING ON...
BUT JUST STAND BY FOR A MINUTE.
I NEED MALCOLM
TO TARGET YOUR POSITION.
THEN I'LL GIVE YOU YOUR ORDERS.
ARCHER TO PHLOX.
THE SOONER THE BETTER.
PHLOX: UNDERSTOOD.
HOW CLOSE CAN YOU GET IT?
REED: I THINK I CAN
SAFELY PLACE IT
TWO METERS INSIDE
THE MOUTH OF THE CAVE.
PHLOX: GOOD.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN!
HELLO?
I'M WAITING FOR THAT ORDER,
BUT I CAN'T WAIT MUCH LONGER!
ARCHER: ALL RIGHT, TRIP.
THIS IS
A MAJOR BREACH OF SECURITY,
BUT I'M GOING
TO HAVE TO TRUST YOU.
TUCKER: GO AHEAD.
ARCHER:
STARFLEET SENT US HERE
TO MAKE CONTACT
WITH A SILICON-BASED LIFE-FORM.
T'POL WAS THE ONLY PERSON
GRANTED CLEARANCE
TO SPEAK WITH THEM.
IT SEEMS
THEY'VE MET VULCANS BEFORE.
TUCKER:
WHY COULDN'T YOU TELL ME THAT?
ARCHER: WHEN A MISSION'S
CLASSIFIED TOP-SECRET,
I DON'T ASK WHY.
TUCKER:
IF IT WAS SO TOP-SECRET,
THEN WHY'D YOU LET US ALL
COME DOWN TO THE SURFACE --
LET US SPEND THE NIGHT?
SATO: THE WINDS.
ARCHER: WE NEVER THOUGHT
THE STORM WOULD DRIVE YOU
INTO THE CAVES.
THAT'S WHERE
THESE ROCK PEOPLE LIVE.
THEY DIDN'T WANT ANYBODY
IN THERE EXCEPT FOR T'POL,
SO THEY'RE NOT TOO HAPPY
RIGHT NOW.
I'M SURE YOU CAN
UNDERSTAND THAT.
THEY'VE EVEN THREATENED
TO DESTROY ENTERPRISE.
NOW, T'POL
NEEDS TO EXPLAIN TO THEM
WHY YOU'RE ALL THERE,
BUT SHE'S NOT
GONNA HAVE MUCH CREDIBILITY
WITH YOU POINTING
A PHASE PISTOL AT HER.
IF THEY AGREE TO LISTEN TO HER,
YOU'LL NEED
TO LOWER YOUR WEAPON.
IF THEY DON'T...
I'M GONNA HAVE MALCOLM
DESTROY THE CAVERN.
SACRIFICING FOUR MORE CREWMEN
IS A SMALL PRICE TO PAY
TO SAVE ENTERPRISE.
TUCKER: I UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: NOW, I'M GONNA ASK HOSHI
TO TELL T'POL EVERYTHING
I JUST TOLD YOU IN VULCAN.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
TUCKER: GO AHEAD.
ARCHER: ENSIGN.
[ CONVERSATION IN VULCAN ]
[ BEEP ]
SHE SAYS PLAYACTING ISN'T
EXACTLY A VULCAN TRADITION,
BUT SHE'LL DO HER BEST.
T'POL: [ SPEAKING VULCAN ]
ARCHER: HOPE SHE
KNOWS THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN STUN AND KILL.
[ BEEP ]
THEY'VE AGREED
TO TALK TO HER, TRIP.
SO LOWER YOUR WEAPON
AND ACT REAL FRIENDLY.
UGH!
MAYWEATHER: NO.
[ GROANS ]
TUCKER: YOU DIDN'T SHOOT ME
LAST NIGHT, DID YOU?
T'POL: I'M AFRAID I DID.
MAYWEATHER: I WAS HOPING IT WAS
ALL JUST A BAD DREAM.
TUCKER: ARE THEY GONE?
T'POL: THEY WERE NEVER HERE.
CUTLER: WHAT?
T'POL: THERE WERE
NO ROCK PEOPLE.
YOU WERE ALL HALLUCINATING.
TUCKER: THE POLLEN?
T'POL: YES.
TUCKER: THEN WHAT ABOUT THAT
SPEECH YOU GAVE TO THE WALL?
T'POL: THE CAPTAIN FELT
THAT IF I PLAYED ALONG,
IT MIGHT HELP PERSUADE YOU
TO LOWER YOUR WEAPON.
YOU'D GROWN INCREASINGLY
ILLOGICAL AND VIOLENT --
SOMETHING ABOUT
SPLITTING ME IN TWO.
TUCKER:
A PRETTY GOOD PERFORMANCE.
LOOK, I KNOW I KIND OF SHOT
MY MOUTH OFF LAST NIGHT.
T'POL: YOU WERE UNDER
THE INFLUENCE OF THE POLLEN.
WE ALL WERE.
TUCKER: CHALLENGE
YOUR PRECONCEPTIONS,
OR THEY'LL CHALLENGE YOU.
T'POL: COMMANDER?
TUCKER: THAT'S SOMETHING
MR. VELIK USED TO SAY --
10TH-GRADE BIOLOGY CLASS.
HE WAS A VULCAN SCIENTIST
WHO CAME TO TEACH US
ABOUT LIFE ON OTHER WORLDS.
I'D NEVER SEEN A VULCAN BEFORE.
NOT UP CLOSE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HE SCARED THE HELL OUT OF ME.
T'POL: PERHAPS IT'S NOT TOO LATE
TO FOLLOW HIS ADVICE.
MAYWEATHER: OW. I MUST'VE
TWISTED UP MY NECK.
HOW'S NOVAKOVICH?
DO WE KNOW?
T'POL: THE CAPTAIN SAYS
HE'S GOING TO BE FINE.
[ SHUTTLEPOD APPROACHING ]
CUTLER: OH...