[ POUNDING ON DOOR ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
TUCKER: MAYBE IT'S JUST ME,
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE
THESE VULCAN STARCHARTS
TAKE ALL THE FUN OUT OF IT.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE EXPLORERS,
AREN'T WE?
ARCHER: THAT'S
THE GENERAL IDEA.
TUCKER: WHERE'S THE EXPLORATION
IN GOING PLACES
PEOPLE HAVE ALREADY BEEN?
ARCHER: WELL, FOR ONE THING,
WE'VE NEVER BEEN
TO THESE PLACES.
FOR ANOTHER,
REMEMBER THAT PROTOSTAR
WE RAN ACROSS LAST WEEK?
TUCKER: YEAH.
ARCHER: I'M NOT SEEING IT HERE.
TUCKER: ARE YOU SAYING
THOSE VULCAN STARCHARTS
AREN'T ALL THAT ACCURATE?
WELL, IF THAT'S TRUE, GOOD LUCK
GETTING THEM TO ADMIT IT.
[ ARCHER LAUGHING ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
YOU WANTED
TO SEE ME, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: AS A MATTER OF FACT,
MR. TUCKER AND I
WERE LOOKING
AT THESE STARCHARTS.
THERE'S A PLANET
A FEW LIGHT-YEARS OFF
OUR CURRENT HEADING.
I'M FAMILIAR WITH IT.
ARCHER: WELL,
THE DATA INDICATES
THERE'S A REMOTE OUTPOST
RIGHT HERE
ON THE NORTHERN HEMISPHERE.
P'JEM.
ARCHER: I TAKE IT THIS P'JEM
IS UNDER VULCAN JURISDICTION?
IT'S AN ANCIENT
SPIRITUAL RETREAT,
A REMOTE SANCTUARY FOR KOLINAHR
AND PEACEFUL MEDITATION.
TUCKER: KOLINAHR?
THE VULCAN PURGING OF EMOTION.
ARCHER: WELL, THAT
SOUNDS INTERESTING.
HOW DO YOU THINK THEY'D
FEEL ABOUT A VISIT?
P'JEM IS A PLACE OF
QUIET CONTEMPLATION, CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT CERTAIN
WE'D BE WELCOME.
TUCKER: IT'S BECAUSE VULCANS
THINK WE SMELL BAD, ISN'T IT?
ARCHER: IT'S NOT EVERY DAY
WE GET A CHANCE
TO SEE AN ANCIENT
VULCAN MONASTERY.
I'D SAY A STOPOVER IS
TOO GOOD TO PASS UP...
UNLESS YOU DISAGREE.
I'LL RESEARCH
THE PROPER PROTOCOLS.
ARCHER: GOOD. ARCHER TO HELM.
TRAVIS: GO AHEAD, SIR.
ARCHER: PREPARE TO LAY IN
A COURSE CORRECTION.
T'POL WILL GIVE YOU
THE COORDINATES.
TRAVIS: UNDERSTOOD.
WELL, YOU MUST
BE LOOKING FORWARD
TO VISITING THE SANCTUARY.
IT WAS THE CAPTAIN'S IDEA.
PHLOX: BUT SUCH AN OPPORTUNITY
TO APPRECIATE
YOUR CULTURAL HISTORY.
IT IS A VULCAN SANCTUARY,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN.
PHLOX: PRECISELY MY POINT.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO INTRODUCE
SOME OF YOUR OWN PEOPLE
TO YOUR NEW CREW.
OH. I BELIEVE I SEE
THE SOURCE OF YOUR MISGIVINGS.
BEING SEEN WITH A HUMAN CREW.
T'POL: IT COULD CREATE
A CERTAIN AWKWARDNESS.
MAY I? HMM.
MMM.
I CONFESS, I FEEL AWKWARD MYSELF
ON THIS SHIP SOMETIMES,
OUT OF PLACE.
BUT WHAT IS THAT VULCAN MOTTO?
UM, INFINITE DIVERSITY--
IN INFINITE COMBINATIONS.
MM! [ CHUCKLES ]
AND WHAT IS DIVERSITY
BUT A CELEBRATION
OF DIFFERENCES?
I WONDER IF YOU MIGHT REMIND ME
OF OUR MISSION ON THIS VESSEL?
PLEASE, INDULGE ME.
[ CHUCKLES ]
OUR MISSION IS
TO MAKE CONTACT
WITH THOSE
WHO HUMANS CONSIDER
NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS.
IN OTHER WORDS,
TO SEEK INFINITE DIVERSITY.
I SUPPOSE SO.
WELL, THEN, IT SEEMS TO ME
A CULTURAL EXCHANGE
BETWEEN YOUR VULCAN BRETHREN
AND YOUR HUMAN CREW
IS SIMPLY A FURTHERANCE
OF THAT MISSION.
[ CHUCKLES ]
TUCKER: THEY DON'T EVEN KNOW
WE'RE COMING?
T'POL: IT WASN'T POSSIBLE
TO HAIL THEM.
THE MONKS CONSIDER
TECHNOLOGY A DISTRACTION
FROM THEIR
SPIRITUAL PURSUITS.
ARCHER: I DON'T LIKE DROPPING IN
ON PEOPLE UNANNOUNCED.
IT WON'T BE A PROBLEM AS LONG AS
WE OBSERVE THE PROPER PROTOCOLS.
WHEN WE ARRIVE, WE'LL BE GREETED
BY A VULCAN ELDER.
YOU SHOULD NOT SPEAK TO HIM
OR ANY MEMBER OF THE ORDER
UNLESS SPOKEN TO FIRST.
IF THEY APPEAR
TO BE MEDITATING,
DO NOT APPROACH THEM
OR ATTEMPT TO MAKE CONVERSATION.
ALSO, MAINTAIN QUIET
AT ALL TIMES,
AND DO NOT TOUCH OR DISTURB
ANY ARTIFACTS, RELICS,
OR ORNAMENTATION.
IF WE ARRIVE AT THEIR TIME
OF COMMUNAL KOLINAHR,
IT'S LIKELY WE'LL
BE TURNED AWAY.
AT THE CONCLUSION
OF OUR VISIT,
WE'LL BE OFFERED
THE STONE OF J'KAH
AS A GESTURE OF SALUTATION.
ACCEPT IT.
THEN BOW SLIGHTLY,
AND OBSERVE A RESPECTFUL SILENCE
FOR APPROXIMATELY 5 SECONDS.
TUCKER: I THOUGHT STARFLEET
TRAINING WAS TOUGH.
TUCKER: YOU SAY THIS IS A PLACE
TO PURGE EMOTIONS?
LOOKS LIKE SOMEBODY HAD
TO PURGE PRETTY BAD.
HE BASHED THE DOOR IN.
T'POL: THE TEMPLE IS ALMOST
3,000 YEARS OLD, COMMANDER.
YOU CAN'T EXPECT IT TO BE
IN PRISTINE CONDITION.
[ BELL CLANGS ]
[T'POL AND MAN WHISPERING]
T'POL: HE SAYS WE HAVE ARRIVED
AT THE TIME OF KOLINAHR.
THE ORDER MUST REMAIN
IN SILENT REFLECTION
THROUGHOUT THE LUNAR CYCLE.
THEY ARE NOT TO BE DISTURBED.
ARCHER: OH, THAT'S TOO BAD.
WELL, AT LEAST WE GOT
TO SEE THE PLACE.
T'POL: YOUR SERVICE HONORS US.
BEFORE WE LEAVE,
MAY I REQUEST
THE OFFERING OF THE J'KAH STONE
FOR MY DISTINGUISHED GUESTS?
MAN: PLEASE WAIT.
ARCHER: IS SOMETHING WRONG?
T'POL: IT'S PROBABLY NOTHING.
ARCHER: BUT?
T'POL: THIS IS THE MAIN ATRIUM.
THERE SHOULD BE MORE THAN ONE
MEMBER OF THE ORDER PRESENT.
AND THE ICON IN THAT SHRINE
IS PERCHED
AT AN ODD ANGLE.
TUCKER: ODDLY PERCHED, HUH?
WE'D BETTER CALL
STARFLEET COMMAND.
T'POL: THAT'S NOT ALL, CAPTAIN.
THE VULCAN ELDER SEEMS...
AGITATED.
TUCKER: YOU CALL THAT AGITATED?
ARCHER: YOU KNOW, I THINK
THE OLDEST MONASTERY
I EVER VISITED
WAS IN NGARI, TIBET,
BUT IT WASN'T NEARLY
AS BIG AS THIS PLACE.
I'VE HEARD IT CAN TAKE DAYS
TO EXPLORE THIS SITE.
IT'D TAKE AT LEAST THAT LONG
TO CLEAN THE PLACE UP.
FORGIVE THE DISARRAY.
KOLINAHR ENCOURAGES
MEMBERS OF OUR ORDER
TO FACE
THEIR VESTIGIAL EMOTIONS.
THE REPERCUSSIONS CAN
SOMETIMES BE VIOLENT.
ELDER: PLEASE.
THIS IS THE STONE OF J'KAH,
WHICH REPRESENTS THE FOUNDATION
OF ALL WE BELIEVE--
A LIFE OF ORDER AND CONTROL
THROUGH LOGIC.
[ SPEAKING VULCAN ]
ARCHER: WHAT'S ALL THAT
MEAN, ANYWAY?
IT IS A TRADITIONAL LITANY,
PASSED DOWN FOR GENERATIONS.
ARCHER: DOES IT MEAN I GET
GOOD LUCK OR SOMETHING?
OH, YOU'RE THINKING
OF THE BLARNEY STONE, CAPTAIN,
OR WHEN YOU PAT
THE BUDDHA'S BELLY.
ARCHER: I GUESS YOU'RE RIGHT.
TOO BAD WE, UH...
DIDN'T BRING A CAMERA,
HUH, COMMANDER?
ELDER: PLEASE,
YOU MUST LEAVE NOW.
TUCKER: YOU EVER BEEN
TO THE SAN FRANCISCO ZOO?
NOW THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU SHOULD SEE.
[ WEAPONS CHARGING ]
ARCHER: FRIENDS OF YOURS?
SOMEHOW I DIDN'T THINK SO.
[ TUCKER SIGHS ]
ALIEN: STOP LOOKING AT ME.
TUCKER: OKAY, OKAY, DON'T GET
YOUR ANTENNAS IN A TWIST.
ALIEN: WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US
ONE OF YOUR PEOPLE WAS ABOARD?
ELDER: IT'S AN EARTH VESSEL.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
ALIEN 2: WHAT DOES THAT MEAN--
EARTH? WHAT IS THAT?
ARCHER: IT'S WHERE WE'RE FROM.
IT'S OUR HOMEWORLD.
ALIEN: WHY DID YOU COME HERE?
ANSWER ME, PINK-SKIN!
ARCHER: THIS PLANET
WAS ALONG OUR COURSE.
WE ONLY CAME TO VISIT
THE SANCTUARY.
ALIEN: LIAR!
WHAT'S YOUR MISSION?
ARE YOU A SUPPLY SHIP
BRINGING THEM
MORE SURVEILLANCE EQUIPMENT?
ARCHER: WE'RE NOT
BRINGING THEM ANYTHING.
ALIEN 2: YOU BROUGHT HER.
ARCHER: SHE'S MY
SCIENCE OFFICER.
ALIEN: SO YOU ADMIT YOU'RE
WORKING WITH THE VULCANS?
ARCHER: I'LL ADMIT I HAVE
A VULCAN SCIENCE OFFICER
AND THAT I CAME HERE
OUT OF CURIOSITY.
NOW IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY ASKING,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
[ ALIEN SCOFFS ]
[ ARCHER GRUNTS ]
TUCKER: HEY!
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH.
WE CAME FOR A VISIT,
THAT'S ALL.
ALIEN: WE SCANNED YOUR SHIP
IN ORBIT.
YOU'RE VERY WELL ARMED FOR
PEOPLE WHO CAME FOR A VISIT.
YOU...AND THE PINK-SKINS
HAVE PROVEN
WHAT WE ALREADY KNEW.
THIS IS FAR MORE
THAN A SANCTUARY.
[ COUGHS ]
ALIEN 2: I'LL ENJOY HAVING YOU
AS A PRISONER.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
TUCKER: NOW, THESE GUYS
ARE AGITATED.
[GROANING ]
THEY'RE ANDORIANS, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE KNOWN FOR THEIR
SUSPICIOUS AND VOLATILE NATURE.
ANDORIANS?
T'POL: YES, SIR.
ELDER: OUR TWO SPECIES ARE
FROM NEIGHBORING SYSTEMS.
WE'VE BEEN IN CONFLICT
FOR MANY YEARS.
T'POL: THEY RESENT
OUR SUPERIOR REASONING
AND OUR TECHNOLOGY.
THEY EVEN BELIEVE
THAT WE INTEND TO MOUNT
AN INVASION
ON THEIR HOMEWORLD.
ELDER: IN ORDER TO
ALLEVIATE TENSIONS,
WE NEGOTIATED A TREATY,
BUT SOME ANDORIAN FACTIONS STILL
BELIEVE WE'RE BENT ON CONQUEST.
WHAT DO THEY WANT
WITH A 3,000-YEAR-OLD TEMPLE?
THEY BELIEVE WE ARE HIDING
A LONG-RANGE SENSOR ARRAY.
THIS IS A PLACE
OF INTROSPECTION, CAPTAIN.
THERE ARE NO SPIES HERE
AND NO TECHNOLOGY.
TUCKER: SO WHAT
ARE YOU GONNA DO,
JUST SIT HERE AND LET THEM
RANSACK THE PLACE?
TYPICALLY, THEY MAKE A GREAT
DISPLAY OF THEIR INDIGNANCE.
WHEN THEY FIND NOTHING,
THEY LEAVE.
THE ANDORIANS WERE HERE
TWICE BEFORE
AND BOTH TIMES LEFT
WITHIN A DAY.
UNFORTUNATELY, YOUR ARRIVAL
HAS AMPLIFIED THEIR SUSPICIONS.
YOU'VE ENDANGERED US ALL.
TUCKER: NO GOOD DEED
GOES UNPUNISHED.
REED: THE SHUTTLE'S SENSORS
SHOULD'VE PICKED IT UP.
HOSHI: THEY WENT
TO VISIT SOME MONKS.
WHY WOULD THEY SCAN
FOR ALIEN SHIPS?
REED: IT SHOULD BE STANDARD
PROCEDURE, THAT'S WHY.
IN ANY EVENT, THERE IT IS.
TRAVIS: THERE WHAT IS?
REED: A VESSEL, NOT VULCAN.
AND IT'S LESS THAN ONE KILOMETER
FROM OUR SHUTTLEPOD.
TRAVIS: NOT A LOT OF ROOM
ON THAT LANDING PLATFORM.
MAYBE THEY'RE JUST
SOME OTHER VISITORS.
REED: WELL, I FOR ONE WOULD LIKE
TO KNOW WHO THESE VISITORS ARE.
AND WHY HAVEN'T WE HEARD
FROM THE LANDING PARTY?
HOSHI: YOU CAN'T EXPECT THEM
TO CHECK IN EVERY 10 MINUTES.
REED: MAYBE THAT SHOULD BE
STANDARD PROCEDURE, AS WELL.
YOU SURE
YOU'RE NOT OVERREACTING?
THEY'RE PROBABLY
JUST TAKING A TOUR,
OBSERVING SOME KIND
OF MEDITATION RITUAL.
[ ARCHER GRUNTS ]
WHERE'S THE SENSOR ARRAY?
FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
THERE ISN'T ONE.
WHERE IS IT?!
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU HUMANS OBVIOUSLY
HAVE EMOTIONS.
I FIND IT CURIOUS
THAT YOU'D SELECT A VULCAN
AS YOUR SCIENCE OFFICER.
BELIEVE ME,
SHE WASN'T MY FIRST CHOICE.
ALIEN: WHY A VULCAN?
ALIEN: WHY A VULCAN?!
SHE WAS ASSIGNED TO US
BY THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND.
ALIEN: YOU TAKE ORDERS
FROM THE HIGH COMMAND?
NO.
FOR THE LAST TIME,
WE JUST CAME TO SEE THE TEMPLE.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPING ]
ARCHER: THAT'S MY SHIP.
ENTERPRISE.
THEY'RE TRYING TO CONTACT.
UGH!
[ BEEPING CONTINUES ]
ALIEN: ENTERPRISE.
REED: YES, I'M LOOKING
FOR CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ALIEN: HE'S A PRISONER
OF THE ANDORIAN IMPERIAL GUARD.
WE KNOW YOU'RE IN COLLABORATION
WITH THE VULCANS.
LET ME TALK TO THE CAPTAIN.
ALIEN: YOUR SHIP IS UNDER
CONSTANT SURVEILLANCE.
ARM YOUR WEAPONS
OR MAKE ANY ATTEMPT
TO APPROACH THE SURFACE,
AND I'LL KILL THE HOSTAGES.
ARCHER: WAIT!
I'VE LOST THE SIGNAL.
TRY T'POL OR COMMANDER TUCKER.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
NO RESPONSE.
REED: HAVE LAUNCH BAY PUT
SHUTTLEPOD 2 ON STANDBY.
TRAVIS: YOU HEARD WHAT HE SAID.
IF WE TRY TO SEND
MORE PEOPLE--
REED: I DON'T TAKE ORDERS
FROM A COM VOICE, ENSIGN,
NOT UNLESS THAT VOICE
BELONGS TO THE CAPTAIN.
TAKE A LOOK
AT THE VULCAN DATABASE.
SEE IF IT HAS ANYTHING
ON THESE ANDORIANS.
AYE, SIR.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
ALIEN: WE'VE SEARCHED ALL THE
CHAMBERS IN THE EASTERN TOWER.
ALIEN 2: HAVE YOU CHECKED
THE LIVING QUARTERS?
ALIEN: NOT YET.
ALIEN: PERHAPS IF WE DECAPITATE
ONE OR TWO OF THOSE MONKS,
HE'LL START TELLING US
THE TRUTH.
ALIEN 2: IS THAT SOMETHING
YOU COULD LIVE WITH, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: I'VE ALREADY
TOLD YOU THE TRUTH.
ELDER: HOW LONG HAVE YOU LIVED
ON THE EARTH SHIP?
T'POL: 9 WEEKS AND 4 DAYS.
ELDER: THE SMELL MUST
BE INTOLERABLE.
T'POL: YOU GET USED TO IT.
AND I WAS GIVEN
A NASAL NUMBING AGENT.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
ARCHER: WHOSE IDEA WAS IT
TO VISIT THIS PLACE?
[ GROANS ]
THESE GUYS ARE SERIOUS.
[ PANTING ]
THEY'RE GONNA START
KILLING YOU PEOPLE
IF THEY DON'T FIND
WHAT THEY'RE LOOKING FOR.
ELDER: THERE IS
NOTHING TO FIND.
ARCHER: I DON'T THINK
THEY'RE BUYING THAT.
NOT THIS TIME.
LOOKS LIKE THERE
ARE 4 OF THEM.
I SAW SOME KIND
OF SCANNING CONSOLE.
THEY TALKED A LOT
ABOUT SEARCHING ROOMS.
TUCKER: YOU'D THINK THEY COULD
FIND WHATEVER IT IS
THEY'RE LOOKING FOR
WITH THOSE ANTENNAS OF THEIRS.
THEY ANSWERED A HAIL
FROM ENTERPRISE.
THEY THREATENED TO KILL US ALL
IF ANYONE ATTEMPTS A RESCUE.
T'POL: MR. REED WOULDN'T
BE THAT RECKLESS.
I DIDN'T RECRUIT
MY TACTICAL OFFICER
TO SIT ON HIS BUTT
WHEN HE'S THREATENED.
THE ANDORIANS SMASHED
OUR COMMUNICATORS.
THE LONGER WE'RE
OUT OF CONTACT,
THE MORE LIKELY
MALCOLM WILL PUT TOGETHER
A LANDING PARTY,
WARNING OR NO WARNING.
TUCKER: KNOWING HIM,
A HEAVILY ARMED LANDING PARTY.
ARCHER: IT'S JUST
A MATTER OF TIME.
SO IF ANYONE HAS A SUGGESTION,
I'M ALL EARS.
NO OFFENSE.
ELDER: THERE IS AN OPTION.
A TRANSMITTER--IT'S VERY OLD.
YOU SAID YOU HAD NO TECHNOLOGY.
ELDER: IT HASN'T BEEN USED
IN MANY YEARS.
IT MAY NOT EVEN BE WORKING.
TUCKER: I NEVER MET A
BUSTED RADIO I COULDN'T FIX.
WHERE IS THIS TRANSMITTER?
VULCAN: IN THE CATACOMBS.
TUCKER: CATACOMBS?
ELDER: PLEASE LISTEN
TO ME, CAPTAIN.
THERE ARE HIDDEN PASSAGES
BENEATH US
WHERE WE KEEP OUR
MOST SACRED RELICS--
OUR HONORED DEAD.
IF THE ANDORIANS DISCOVER THEM,
THEY WILL DAMAGE OUR CULTURE
IN WAYS YOU CAN'T
BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND.
TUCKER: FOR PEOPLE
WITHOUT EMOTION,
YOU SURE HAVE A FLAIR
FOR THE DRAMATIC.
[ GASPS ]
MASTER HAADOK,
ONE OF THE FOUNDERS OF P'JEM.
THE TRANSMITTER'S THIS WAY.
FELLAS.
WHAT'S DOWN THERE?
VULCAN: THE RELIQUARY.
OUR MOST SACRED ARTIFACTS
ARE KEPT THERE.
THIS IS THE TRANSMITTER.
LOOKS LIKE
A KRELLIDE POWER CELL.
ELDER: THERE IS ONE TO SPARE.
TUCKER: NO, THANKS.
IT'LL JUST GET IN MY WAY.
ELDER: IT'S ONLY GOING
TO GET COLDER.
ARCHER: YOU TAKE IT.
T'POL: YOU NEED IT
MORE THAN I DO.
ARCHER: DO THE ANDORIANS
HAVE A TRANSPORTER?
T'POL: NO.
ARCHER: THAT GIVES US
THE ELEMENT OF SURPRISE.
WE COULD BRING AN ASSAULT
TEAM RIGHT INTO THE ATRIUM.
T'POL: THE SOUND OF
THE TRANSPORTER ALONE
WOULD ALERT THE GUARDS.
THEY'D START FIRING BEFORE
THE TEAM WAS FULLY RESEQUENCED.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT THIS ROOM?
BY THE TIME THE ANDORIANS
DETECTED THE TRANSPORT,
WE'D BE ARMED AND READY.
T'POL: FOR WHAT?
A FIREFIGHT IN CLOSE QUARTERS,
WITH A DOZEN MONKS AT RISK?
IF YOU'VE GOT
ANY BETTER IDEAS...
THERE'S ROOM IN HERE.
T'POL: I'M FINE.
YOU'RE FREEZING.
IT'S BEEN 24 HOURS
SINCE I TOOK
MY NASAL NUMBING AGENT.
THE COLD IS PREFERABLE
TO THE ODOR.
COME ON.
T'POL: AN ARMED ASSAULT WOULD
PUT ALL OF OUR LIVES AT RISK,
NOT TO MENTION THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE SANCTUARY ITSELF.
ARCHER: I'D SAY OUR LIVES
ARE ALREADY AT RISK.
T'POL: TENSIONS BETWEEN ANDORIA
AND VULCAN ARE HIGH.
ANY CASUALTIES WOULD
ONLY MAKE MATTERS WORSE.
ARCHER: IT SEEMS LIKE YOU'RE
LETTING THEM WALK ALL OVER YOU.
THEY COME IN HERE,
THEY SMASH YOUR RELICS,
THEY BEAT UP YOUR PEOPLE.
THEN YOU JUST SIT BACK AND
WAIT FOR THEM TO WALK AWAY?
T'POL: WE DON'T BELIEVE
IN RESPONDING
TO VIOLENCE WITH VIOLENCE.
ARCHER: I ADMIRE YOUR ETHICS,
BUT RIGHT NOW,
A LITTLE VIOLENCE MIGHT HELP.
T'POL: YOU'RE BEGINNING
TO SOUND LIKE AN ANDORIAN.
ARCHER: YOU KNOW, I CAME HERE
HOPING TO GAIN A LITTLE INSIGHT
INTO THE VULCAN MIND.
IT LOOKS LIKE I'M GETTING IT.
YOU PEOPLE THINK YOU'RE
SO DAMNED ENLIGHTENED.
PROBLEM?
I'D LIKE TO FIND
A PEACEFUL SOLUTION, TOO,
BUT I DON'T THINK
THAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
HOWEVER WE END UP
DEALING WITH THIS,
I NEED TO KNOW I
CAN COUNT ON YOU.
T'POL: ARE YOU QUESTIONING
MY LOYALTY?
ARCHER: I JUST WANT TO KNOW
WHERE WE STAND.
T'POL: I HAVE NEVER
DISOBEYED YOUR ORDERS.
TRAVIS: SIR, YOU'RE WEARING
A HOLE IN THE DECK PLATING.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
REED: WHAT IS IT?
TRANSMISSION FROM THE SURFACE.
IT'S A MODULATED E.M. SIGNAL,
VERY WEAK.
REED: PUT IT THROUGH.
TUCKER: ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS COMMANDER TUCKER.
REPEAT-- ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS ENTERPRISE. WE CAN
BARELY READ YOU, COMMANDER.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
TUCKER: GUESS YOU HEARD.
WE KIND OF WALKED INTO
A HOSTAGE SITUATION.
THE WHOLE PLACE HAS BEEN
TAKEN OVER BY ANDORIANS.
REED: ANDORIANS, YES.
I'VE BEEN READING ABOUT THEM
IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
MILITARISTIC, BLUE-SKINNED?
TUCKER: THAT'S THEM.
REED: WELL, WHAT DO THEY WANT?
TUCKER: THEY SEEM
TO THINK THIS PLACE IS
SOME KIND OF A SPY STATION.
THEY'RE LOOKING
FOR A SENSOR ARRAY.
THE CAPTAIN SAYS TO SIT TIGHT.
HE DOESN'T WANT TO PROVOKE THEM
ANY MORE THAN WE ALREADY HAVE.
HE ALSO SAID TO TELL YOU
WE'RE WORKING ON A WAY
OUT OF HERE.
ARE YOU CERTAIN
WE CAN'T NEGOTIATE?
THE CAPTAIN CAME BACK
FROM HIS LAST NEGOTIATION
WITH A FACE FULL OF BRUISES.
TUCKER: WE'LL BE IN TOUCH.
UNDERSTOOD.
ARCHER: DO ANY OF THESE TUNNELS
LEAD TO THE OUTSIDE?
ELDER: NO.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT
THIS RELIQUARY?
VULCAN: NO ONE'S
ENTERED IT IN YEARS.
ELDER: TO DO SO
WOULD BE BLASPHEMY.
TUCKER: I SAW AN OLD STAIRWELL
DOWN THERE,
MAYBE A METER WIDE.
IT WAS RIGHT ABOUT HERE.
T'POL: THAT WOULD ALMOST BE
DIRECTLY BENEATH THE ATRIUM.
TUCKER: THERE WERE 3 DIM LIGHTS
COMING FROM THE TOP.
IT LOOKED SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
ALIEN: HOW MANY TIMES DO WE
HAVE TO SEARCH THE SAME ROOMS?
ALIEN 2: ARE YOU LOSING FAITH
IN OUR MISSION?
ALIEN: WE'VE LOOKED EVERYWHERE.
WE'VE RUN A THOUSAND SCANS!
ALIEN 2: THE VULCANS
ARE VERY DECEPTIVE.
IT'S HERE. I'M SURE OF IT.
IF WE BACK DOWN NOW,
EVERYTHING WE'VE FOUGHT FOR
IS MEANINGLESS!
IF NOTHING ELSE,
REMEMBER THAT, KEVAL.
TUCKER: HEY!
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
HELLO?
ANYBODY OUT THERE?
ARCHER: I NEED TO SPEAK
WITH YOU ALONE.
I HAVE SOME INFORMATION
FOR YOU.
ALIEN: WHAT IS IT?
ARCHER: WELL, FOR ONE THING,
I NEEDED SOME FRESH AIR.
YOU EVER BEEN STUCK IN A ROOM
FULL OF VULCANS FOR 12 HOURS?
ALIEN: THE INFORMATION.
ARCHER: I'LL BET THEIR ROBES
HAVEN'T BEEN WASHED
SINCE THE TIME OF SURAK.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF HIM?
VULCAN PHILOSOPHER.
HE'S THE ONE WHO GOT EVERYBODY
TO START PURGING THEIR EMOTIONS.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I HAVE LEARNED
REALLY A LOT SINCE I GOT HERE.
[ GROANING ]
ALIEN: WHAT DID YOU
COME TO TELL US?
ARCHER: WELL, THAT DEPENDS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO KNOW?
OH!
ALL RIGHT.
INFORMATION.
DID YOU KNOW THAT...
OVER 70% OF THE ORGANISMS
ON MY HOMEWORLD ARE BACTERIA?
WHAT?
HERE'S SOMETHING
I THINK YOU'LL FIND INTERESTING.
THERE WAS A MAN IN CANTON, OHIO,
WHO ONCE ROLLED
A BALL OF STRING
OVER 6 METERS IN DIAMETER.
[ GROANING ]
HE'S WASTING OUR TIME.
TAKE HIM BACK!
THERE WAS A FAMOUS ASTRONOMER
ON EARTH...
TYCHO BRAHE.
HE LOST HIS NOSE IN A DUEL...
[ LAUGHS ]
...OVER A MATH EQUATION!
UGH!
ALIEN: YOU MUST ENJOY PAIN.
ARCHER: PLEASE.
PLEASE, I CAN'T STAND ANOTHER
MINUTE WITH THE VULCANS!
PLEASE!
[ ARCHER GROANING ]
A LIGHT AT THE END
OF THE TUNNEL.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO, COMMANDER.
YES, SIR.
ELDER: I DON'T HAVE
TO TELL YOU, CAPTAIN,
WE DON'T CONDONE THESE ACTIONS
YOU ARE ABOUT TO TAKE.
ARCHER: NO, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO TELL ME.
JUST TRY AND STAY
OUT OF THE WAY,
AND EVERYTHING WILL
WORK OUT FINE.
REED: PHASE PISTOLS ON STUN.
CREWMAN: STUN, SIR?
REED: THE CAPTAIN'S INSTRUCTIONS
WERE QUITE EXPLICIT.
REED: IT'S A CONSOLE, ENSIGN.
IT WON'T BITE.
HOSHI: NO, IT'LL JUST
SCRAMBLE YOUR MOLECULES.
REED: CREWMAN?
CREWMAN: WE'VE, UH...
HEARD STORIES, SIR.
IT MIGHT NOT BE SAFE.
REED: I'VE HEARD
THE SAME STORIES.
NOW GET UP HERE.
COORDINATES SET?
HOSHI: AYE, SIR.
REED: THEN ENERGIZE...
BEFORE WE CHANGE OUR MINDS.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
ALIEN: WHAT IS IT?
ALIEN 2: SOME KIND OF
ENERGY FLUCTUATION.
ALIEN: WE DETECTED
AN ENERGY SURGE.
IT CAME FROM THIS CHAMBER.
T'POL: PERHAPS YOU HAVE
FAULTY EQUIPMENT.
ALIEN: OR PERHAPS YOU HAVE
EQUIPMENT WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
WATCH THEM.
REED: THIS IS IT.
ALIEN: MOST VULCANS
SMELL OF DUST.
BUT YOU'RE DIFFERENT.
TUCKER: SOMETHING SURE SMELLS.
DID YOU SAY SOMETHING,
PINK-SKIN?!
KEVAL: THIS CAN'T BE RIGHT.
I'M DETECTING
3 NEW BIO-SIGNS,
ALL HUMAN.
ALIEN: WHERE ARE THEY?
KEVAL: THEY'RE
WITHIN 20 METERS.
ALIEN: WHERE?!
KEVAL: I CAN'T
PINPOINT THE SIGNAL.
ALIEN: TRY BOOSTING
THE PROXIMITY SENSORS.
ALIEN: I'VE HEARD ABOUT
YOUR MATING RITUALS...
THAT VULCAN WOMEN
FORCE THEIR MEN
TO FIGHT EACH OTHER
TO THE DEATH.
WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO KILL SOMEONE FOR YOU?
ARCHER: LEAVE HER ALONE.
ALIEN: WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO KILL HIM?
ALIEN: FIND THEM!
KEVAL: THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
[ TUCKER GRUNTING ]
REED: WILL YOU BE ALL RIGHT?
CREWMAN: GO AHEAD.
I'LL COVER HERE.
KEVAL!
REED: THIS WAY.
[ ALIEN GRUNTING ]
UGH!
REED: TWO OF THEM GOT AWAY.
THEY WENT DOWN
INTO THE CATACOMBS.
I HOPE YOU'RE PLEASED, CAPTAIN.
YOU'VE TURNED A PLACE
OF SOLITUDE INTO A WAR ZONE.
ARCHER: WHERE ARE
THE PHASE PISTOLS?
REED: HERE, SIR.
ARCHER: IF HE WAKES UP,
STUN HIM AGAIN.
LET'S GO.
VULCAN: I'M GOING WITH YOU.
ELDER: VIOLENCE IS
NO LONGER OUR WAY.
WE MUST PROTECT WHAT IS OURS.
THEY'RE DOWN THIS PASSAGE.
30 METERS.
VULCAN: IT LEADS
TO THE RELIQUARY.
ONLY MEMBERS OF THE HIGH ORDER
ARE ALLOWED TO GO INSIDE.
ARCHER: WE'LL DO OUR BEST
NOT TO LOOK AT ANYTHING.
VULCAN: I CAN'T
PERMIT IT, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WHAT WOULD
YOU SUGGEST WE DO?
VULCAN: I'LL
DISARM THEM MYSELF.
ARCHER: YOU EVER
USE ONE OF THOSE?
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
THE ANDORIANS HAVE SEEN
YOUR SACRED RELICS.
A COUPLE HUMANS WON'T MAKE
MUCH OF A DIFFERENCE.
CAPTAIN.
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS!
ARCHER: I DON'T BELIEVE THIS.
ARCHER: DOES THAT THING
HAVE IMAGING SENSORS?
T'POL: YES.
TAKE ALL THE PICTURES YOU CAN.
VULCAN: PLACE YOUR WEAPONS
ON THE GROUND.
I...WILL KILL HIM IF NECESSARY.
GIVE THAT TO ME.
ARCHER: UGH!
REED: VIOLENCE IN
A SANCTUARY, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: VERY DISRESPECTFUL,
BUT, BOY, DID IT FEEL GOOD.
ALL THIS TIME, THEY'VE BEEN
CALLING THESE MONKS LIARS,
AND ALL THIS TIME
THEY'VE BEEN RIGHT.
REED: THEY'VE GOT ENOUGH
EQUIPMENT DOWN THERE TO SEE
WHAT ANY ANDORIAN IS
HAVING FOR BREAKFAST.
T'POL: I'VE COMPLETED MY SCANS.
ARCHER: GIVE IT TO HIM.
T'POL: SIR?
YOU GOT WHAT YOU CAME FOR.
NOW GET OUT OF HERE.
HOW DO WE KNOW YOU
WON'T ATTACK OUR VESSEL?
THE VULCANS VIOLATED
YOUR TREATY.
YOUR PEOPLE
OUGHT TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
ARCHER: YOU HAVE
A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
YOUR COMMUNICATOR.
T'POL TO ENTERPRISE.
TRAVIS: GO AHEAD.
THE ANDORIAN SHIP
WILL BE LEAVING THE SURFACE
MOMENTARILY.
T'POL: THEY'RE FREE TO GO.
TRAVIS: ACKNOWLEDGED.
ALIEN: WE'RE IN YOUR DEBT.
THANKS FOR THE TOUR.