[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ARCHER: MORNING, EVERYONE.
-MORNING, SIR.
ARCHER: WHAT HAVE WE GOT TODAY?
T'POL: WE'VE DETECTED
SEVERAL PHENOMENON.
A J'RAL-CLASS
SUPERNOVA REMNANT
APPROXIMATELY 3 LIGHT-YEARS
OFF OUR COURSE.
THAT'S INTERESTING.
WHAT ELSE?
T'POL: A CLUSTER
OF 3 NEUTRON STARS.
VERY UNUSUAL.
TUCKER: HOW ABOUT THAT?
3 STONE-COLD STARS.
PRETTY EXCITING, HUH?
ANYTHING ELSE?
TUCKER: THERE IS
ONE OTHER THING
MIGHT BE WORTH SWINGING BY
TO TAKE A LOOK.
A MINSHARA-CLASS PLANET...
ABOUT 4 1/2 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
ANY LIFE SIGNS?
ONLY ABOUT 500 MILLION.
[ CHUCKLING ]
TUCKER: IF OUR SCANS ARE RIGHT,
IT LOOKS LIKE THERE'S
A WHOLE CIVILIZATION
DOWN THERE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
ARCHER: YOU MIGHT HAVE PUT THAT
ON THE TOP OF THE LIST.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: PUT US INTO ORBIT
AT 500 KILOMETERS.
REED: I'M NOT PICKING UP
ANY OTHER SHIPS OR SATELLITES.
TRAVIS: SHOULD WE HAIL THEM?
HOSHI: WHO?
I'M PICKING UP DOZENS OF CITIES
ON EACH CONTINENT.
ARCHER: LET'S HOLD OFF
A SECOND.
WE DON'T KNOW
WHETHER THEY'RE USING
HIGH-BAND FREQUENCIES
OR SMOKE SIGNALS.
T'POL: THE LATTER'S
MORE LIKELY.
I'M NOT DETECTING
ANY E.M. TRANSMISSIONS.
PREINDUSTRIAL?
ARCHER: LET'S TAKE
A CLOSER LOOK.
DO YOU SEE THAT?
JUST OFF THE COAST.
HOSHI: I'VE GOT IT.
TUCKER: LOOKS LIKE
AN OLD CLIPPER SHIP.
YEAH, IT'S ALMOST LIKE
TRAVELING BACK IN TIME.
TUCKER: I CANNOT WAIT
TO GET DOWN THERE.
I'D ADVISE AGAINST THAT.
IT'S STANDARD PROTOCOL TO WAIT
UNTIL A SOCIETY
DEVELOPS WARP DRIVE
BEFORE INITIATING
FIRST CONTACT.
THOSE ARE VULCAN PROTOCOLS,
NOT HUMAN.
STARFLEET WOULD BE WISE
TO ADOPT THEM.
THERE'S NO WAY TO KNOW
HOW OUR ARRIVAL
WOULD AFFECT THE EVOLUTION
OF THEIR SOCIETY.
SO, WHAT ARE YOU
SUGGESTING WE DO?
OUR SENSORS CAN GATHER
A GREAT DEAL OF DATA FROM ORBIT.
GIVE ME A TIGHTER VIEW
OF THE CITY, HOSHI.
CAN YOU GET TIGHT ENOUGH
TO SEE THEIR FACES?
FREEZE THAT.
ARCHER: THEY DON'T
LOOK SO DIFFERENT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, TRIP?
TUCKER: I THINK
YOU'RE RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
YOU'D BE RECOGNIZED IMMEDIATELY
AS OUTSIDERS.
ARCHER: NOT IF
WE LOOK LIKE THEM.
STARFLEET COULD HAVE SENT
A PROBE OUT HERE
TO MAKE MAPS AND TAKE PICTURES,
BUT THEY DIDN'T.
THEY SENT US...
SO THAT WE COULD EXPLORE
WITH OUR OWN SENSES.
[ HOSHI CHUCKLES ]
ARCHER: YOU OKAY?
HOSHI: THE ACOUSTIC RELAY
IS PICKING UP
DOZENS OF LANGUAGES.
I COULD SPEND THE NEXT 10 YEARS
STUDYING THIS PLACE.
ARCHER: WELL, LET'S
HEAR SOME OF IT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HOSHI: IT'LL TAKE A WHILE
TO WORK OUT
A TRANSLATION MATRIX
FOR ALL OF THEM.
WE'LL BE ABLE
TO NARROW IT DOWN FOR YOU
ONCE WE PICK A LANDING SITE.
I DID FIND ONE WORD YOU MIGHT
WANT TO REMEMBER--AKAALI.
IT'S THE NAME
OF THEIR SPECIES.
ARCHER: A FARM?
IT'S REMOTE
AND SPARSELY POPULATED.
IF YOU'RE EXPOSED,
THERE'S A REDUCED RISK
OF CULTURAL CONTAMINATION.
ARCHER: THIS MUST BE
WHY ALIENS ARE ALWAYS
LANDING IN CORNFIELDS.
SO...WHO DO WE SEND FIRST?
PHLOX: IT SHOULD STAND UP
TO SCRUTINY
AS LONG AS YOU DON'T,
UH, LOOK TOO CLOSE, HMM?
HERE. SEE FOR YOURSELF.
HOSHI: IT ITCHES.
PHLOX: UNH-UNH-UNH!
YOU MUSTN'T TOUCH IT, ENSIGN.
THE IRRITATION WILL SUBSIDE.
ARE YOU SURE I'M
THE RIGHT PERSON FOR THIS?
ARCHER: IF THE TRANSLATOR
GOES DOWN,
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO HANDLE
YOURSELF BETTER THAN ANY OF US.
PHLOX: THE ANTERIOR CRESTS
AREN'T QUITE SYMMETRICAL.
I'LL JUST ADD A LITTLE MORE
DEFINITION TO THE RIGHT SIDE.
ARCHER: WE DON'T NEED IT
TO BE TOO PERFECT.
PHLOX: OF COURSE, CAPTAIN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
T'POL: T'POL TO ARCHER.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: PLEASE REPORT
TO THE BRIDGE.
ARCHER: IS THERE A PROBLEM?
T'POL: I'M DETECTING
NEUTRINO EMISSIONS
FROM A CITY
ON THE EASTERN CONTINENT.
ARCHER: WHAT'S CAUSING IT?
POSSIBLY AN ANTIMATTER REACTOR.
ARCHER: THESE PEOPLE DON'T
EVEN HAVE INDOOR PLUMBING.
HOSHI: MAYBE SOME OF THEM
ARE MORE ADVANCED THAN OTHERS.
OR MAYBE WE'RE NOT
THE FIRST VISITORS.
WHAT ABOUT
NONINDIGENOUS BIO-SIGNS?
I'M NOT READING ANY, BUT AT THIS
RANGE, IT'S HARD TO BE CERTAIN.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
TRIP, T'POL, LET'S HEAD
DOWN TO SICK BAY.
ARCHER: LET
THE QUARTERMASTER KNOW
WE'LL NEED
3 MORE SETS OF CLOTHING.
TUCKER: MY FEET WOULD BE A LOT
HAPPIER IN MY OWN BOOTS.
[ ARCHER LAUGHS ]
ARCHER: WHAT'S THIS?
HOSHI: IDENTIFICATION PAPERS.
EVERYONE IN THE CITY
HAS TO CARRY THEM.
TUCKER: T'POL.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ BEEPING ]
HOSHI: T'POL.
ARCHER: OVER HERE.
TUCKER: I'VE GOT IT, TOO.
THE REACTOR'S ABOUT 8 METERS
UNDER THIS BUILDING.
ARCHER: LOOKS LIKE
SOME KIND OF A CURIO SHOP.
ARCHER: I GUESS WE'LL HAVE
TO WAIT TILL MORNING.
TUCKER: THERE COULD BE A LOT
MORE PEOPLE AROUND THEN.
MIGHT BE EASIER TO GET
A LOOK AT THIS THING TONIGHT.
ARCHER: EXCEPT WE'RE ON
THE WRONG SIDE OF THIS DOOR.
TUCKER: NOT FOR LONG.
ARCHER: 78 LIGHT-YEARS
TO GET HERE,
AND OUR FIRST ACT IS
BREAKING AND ENTERING.
MAYBE YOU DON'T HAVE TO MENTION
THIS PART IN YOUR LOG.
TRIP.
GOING AS FAST AS I CAN.
[ FOOTSTEPS PASSING ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'POL: GO AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: I THINK WE'VE FOUND
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
T'POL: ACKNOWLEDGED. WE'LL MEET
AT YOUR COORDINATES.
TUCKER: BACK HERE.
[ DOOR OPENS, CREAKS ]
TUCKER: THE NEUTRINO EMISSIONS
ARE OFF THE METER.
IT'S GOT TO BE THROUGH HERE.
TUCKER: IT'S SOME KIND
OF MAGNETIC BARRIER.
ARCHER: CAN YOU DISABLE IT?
TUCKER: I'LL TRY.
[ CREAK ]
WOMAN: WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT DID YOU DO TO THAT DOOR?
TUCKER: NOTHING. HONEST.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE.
ARCHER: YOU DON'T NEED
TO POINT THAT WEAPON AT US.
WE'RE COLLECTORS.
WE'RE PICKING UP AN ANTIQUE.
A REAL COLLECTOR WOULD HAVE
WAITED UNTIL THE SHOP WAS OPEN.
YOU'RE NOT HERE
TO PICK UP ANY ANTIQUES.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING
THIS SHOP FOR WEEKS.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
YOUR EVENING DELIVERIES.
ARCHER: DELIVERIES?
PEOPLE ARE GETTING SICK.
SOME ARE EVEN DYING BECAUSE
OF WHAT'S GOING ON IN HERE.
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
MOVE AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
UGH!
WAS THAT NECESSARY?
T'POL: SHE WAS ARMED.
LET'S TRY NOT TO SHOOT ANYONE
ELSE WHILE WE'RE HERE, OKAY?
T'POL: I'LL TRY.
ARCHER: THE REACTOR
SIGNATURE'S COMING
FROM THE OTHER SIDE
OF THAT DOOR,
BUT IT'S PROTECTED
BY SOME KIND OF ENERGY FIELD.
T'POL: WE SHOULD GO.
IT'LL BE DAWN SOON.
TUCKER: WHAT ABOUT HER?
WE CAN'T JUST LEAVE HER HERE.
HOSHI.
HOSHI: HER NAME'S RIAAN.
SHE'S AN APOTHECARY.
I'LL MEET YOU
BACK AT THE SHUTTLE.
RIAAN: WHAT DID YOU DO TO ME?
ARCHER: NOTHING.
YOU JUST COLLAPSED.
THAT'S THE SECOND LIE
YOU'VE TOLD ME.
YOU'RE NOT VERY GOOD AT IT.
RIAAN: WHY DID YOU
BRING ME BACK HERE?
DID GAROS TELL YOU TO?
ARE YOU WORKING FOR HIM?
ARCHER: GAROS?
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHO I'M TALKING ABOUT?
HE OWNS THE SHOP
YOU BROKE INTO.
ARCHER: I'M NOT
WORKING FOR ANYONE.
I JUST WANTED TO MAKE SURE
YOU GOT HOME ALL RIGHT.
RIAAN: WAIT.
IF YOU DON'T WORK FOR HIM,
WHAT WERE YOU DOING IN THERE?
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
THERE'S SOMETHING STRANGE
GOING ON IN THAT SHOP.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT EXACTLY,
BUT I'M TRYING
TO FIGURE IT OUT.
I'M AN INVESTIGATOR...
FROM ANOTHER CITY.
WHICH CITY? WHO SENT YOU?
I CAN'T TELL YOU
ANY MORE THAN THAT,
NOT RIGHT NOW.
I SUPPOSE TELLING ME NOTHING
IS BETTER THAN ANOTHER LIE.
MY COLLEAGUE'S WAITING FOR ME.
I'VE GOT TO GO.
YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT A SICKNESS.
I WANTED TO COME BACK TOMORROW
AND TALK TO YOU ABOUT IT.
WILL YOU BE HERE?
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME YOUR NAME.
JON.
HOW FAR AWAY IS THIS CITY?
EVEN IF WE FLATTEN THE BUILDING
WITH A TORPEDO BARRAGE,
IT PROBABLY WOULDN'T MAKE A DENT
IN THAT ENERGY FIELD.
ARCHER:
WHAT ABOUT THE SHOP ITSELF?
CAN YOU SCAN UNDERNEATH IT?
THAT'S STRANGE.
SENSORS AREN'T PICKING UP
ANYTHING UNDER THE SHOP--
NO BASEMENT, NO BEDROCK.
IT'S LIKE THE BUILDING'S
SITTING ON NOTHING AT ALL.
TUCKER: THERE MUST BE SOME KIND
OF DAMPENING FIELD IN PLACE.
KEEP YOUR SENSORS
LOCKED ON THAT SHOP.
IF YOU NOTICE ANYTHING ELSE
OUT OF THE ORDINARY,
LET ME KNOW RIGHT AWAY.
REED: UNDERSTOOD.
THAT WOMAN--RIAAN--
SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT PEOPLE GETTING SICK.
HOSHI: I THINK WE MAY HAVE
SEEN SOME OF THEM.
MOTTLED SKIN,
LESIONS ON THEIR FACES.
TUCKER: IF WE CAN GET ONE
OF THESE PEOPLE TO THE SHIP,
DR. PHLOX MIGHT BE ABLE TO TELL
US WHAT'S WRONG WITH THEM.
T'POL: I'D ADVISE AGAINST THAT.
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
THE FEAR OF ALIEN ABDUCTION
CAUSED A GREAT DEAL
OF APPREHENSION
ON YOUR PLANET FOR CENTURIES.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD TALK
TO THE SHOPKEEPER FIRST.
MAN: WELCOME, GENTLEMEN.
IF I DON'T HAVE
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR,
I'M CERTAIN I CAN FIND
SOMEONE WHO DOES.
CAN I HELP YOU?
ARCHER: WE NOTICED THE ANTIQUES
IN THE WINDOW.
MY FRIEND HERE IS
AN AMATEUR COLLECTOR.
MAN: WERE YOU LOOKING
FOR SOMETHING IN PARTICULAR?
TUCKER: UM...
THESE ARE INTERESTING.
MAN: YOU WON'T FIND
A MORE VARIED COLLECTION
IN THE ENTIRE CITY.
THIS IS THE PRIDE
OF MY ENTIRE COLLECTION.
WHO'S IT SUPPOSED TO BE?
DRAYLAN, THE MYTHICAL RULER
OF THE AFTERWORLD.
OH.
YOU'RE NOT FROM THIS PROVINCE,
ARE YOU?
ARCHER: NO.
AND NEITHER ARE YOU.
YOUR DNA DOESN'T MATCH ANY OTHER
LIFE-FORM ON THIS PLANET.
NOR DOES YOURS.
MAN: I SEE WHY YOU HAVE
A FONDNESS FOR MASKS.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
WE'RE EXPLORERS
FROM THE PLANET EARTH.
EARTH? I NEVER HEARD OF IT.
HOW DID YOU KNOW I WAS HERE?
WE PICKED UP THE SIGNATURE
FROM YOUR REACTOR.
ARCHER: NOW THAT YOU KNOW
WHO WE ARE,
MAYBE YOU COULD TELL US
WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE.
I'M AN EXPLORER AS WELL.
AT LEAST, I USED TO BE.
I'M FROM THE MALURIAN SYSTEM.
TWO YEARS AGO, I LED A SURVEY
MISSION TO STUDY THE AKAALI.
WE HAD NO PLANS
TO REMAIN HERE,
BUT, AFTER A FEW MONTHS,
I FOUND MYSELF
QUITE TAKEN WITH THESE PEOPLE,
SO I DECIDED TO STAY.
ARCHER: IF YOU ENJOY
THE SIMPLE LIFE SO MUCH,
WHY DO YOU HAVE AN ANTIMATTER
REACTOR IN YOUR BASEMENT?
MAN: THERE'S NOTHING NEFARIOUS
ABOUT IT, I ASSURE YOU.
THE REACTOR POWERS
A FABRICATION DEVICE.
IT ALLOWS ME TO MAKE
FOOD AND CLOTHING.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE HEARD,
BUT THERE'S AN ILLNESS
SPREADING THROUGH THIS AREA.
SOME PEOPLE SEEM TO THINK
YOU'RE THE CAUSE OF IT.
I SEE YOU'VE MET
OUR APOTHECARY.
YOU KNOW HER?
SHE'S BEEN MAKING
BASELESS ACCUSATIONS
AGAINST ME FOR MONTHS.
THERE'S A LETHAL VIRUS
SPREADING AMONG THE AKAALI,
BUT IT'S INDIGENOUS.
I CERTAINLY DIDN'T
BRING IT HERE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THESE PEOPLE DON'T HAVE
THE MEDICAL TECHNOLOGY
TO CURE IT.
SO THIS WOMAN BLAMES
THE NEWCOMER, ME.
ARCHER: IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND,
WE'D LIKE TO TAKE A LOOK
AT THIS REACTOR OF YOURS.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
PERHAPS SOME OTHER TIME,
CAPTAIN.
EXCUSE ME.
WELCOME.
IF I DON'T HAVE
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR,
I'M CERTAIN I CAN FIND
SOMEONE WHO DOES.
GENTLEMEN.
ARCHER: HIS REACTOR'S GOT
AN AWFUL LOT OF POWER
FOR A FABRICATION DEVICE.
TUCKER: HE COULD PROBABLY
FEED AND CLOTHE HALF
THE CONTINENT WITH IT.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'POL: GO AHEAD..
ARCHER: HOW SOON
CAN YOU MEET US?
[ KNOCK AT DOOR ]
YES?
ARCHER: HELLO AGAIN.
RIAAN: HELLO.
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND?
ARCHER: HER NAME'S T'POL.
SHE'S HELPING ME
INVESTIGATE GAROS' SHOP.
YOU TWO HAVE
SOMETHING IN COMMON.
T'POL IS A SCIENTIST,
AS WELL.
T'POL: YOUR FACILITY'S
IMPRESSIVE.
WOULD YOU MIND?
RIAAN: IF YOU'RE CAREFUL
NOT TO TOUCH ANYTHING.
YOU TWO ARE FROM
THE SAME PROVINCE?
ARCHER: NOT EXACTLY.
MUST BE DIFFICULT
TO MAKE FRIENDS
WHEN YOU KEEP
SO MUCH TO YOURSELF.
ARCHER: I'M SORRY.
I DON'T MEAN TO BE EVASIVE.
RIAAN: YES, YOU DO.
TURN DOWN THAT FLAME, PLEASE.
ARCHER: I WAS HOPING YOU COULD
TELL US A LITTLE BIT MORE
ABOUT THIS ILLNESS.
RIAAN: WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
WHY YOU WERE IN GAROS' SHOP?
WE WERE TRYING TO GET
INTO THE BASEMENT.
WE THINK THERE'S SOME KIND
OF MACHINE THERE,
SOMETHING HE'S NOT
SUPPOSED TO HAVE.
WHAT KIND OF MACHINE?
ARCHER: WE'RE NOT SURE,
BUT IT MAY BE
INDIRECTLY CONNECTED
TO THIS EPIDEMIC.
IF YOU TELL US
WHAT YOU KNOW,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP.
RIAAN: I CAN'T TELL YOU MUCH.
PEOPLE ARE DYING,
AND I CAN'T DETERMINE WHY.
DROP THIS IN THE WATER,
CAREFULLY.
I LEARNED OF THE EPIDEMIC
ABOUT 18 MONTHS AGO.
MY BROTHER WAS ONE
OF THE FIRST VICTIMS.
ARCHER: I'M SORRY.
RIAAN: AT FIRST,
I THOUGHT IT WAS
SOME KIND OF
AIRBORNE CONTAGION.
BUT IT NEVER SPREAD BEYOND
THIS PART OF THE CITY.
I'VE SAMPLED THE SOIL,
THE WATER.
I CAN'T FIND ANYTHING
OUT OF THE ORDINARY.
ARCHER: WHY DO YOU BELIEVE
THIS GAROS IS INVOLVED?
THE FIRST CASES
OCCURRED HERE...
A FEW HUNDRED METERS
FROM HIS SHOP.
THAT WAS JUST ONE MONTH
AFTER HE ARRIVED.
ARCHER: YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT EVENING DELIVERIES.
RIAAN: EVERY FEW NIGHTS,
SOMEONE CARRIES CRATES
FROM HIS SHOP TO DIFFERENT
PLACES OUTSIDE THE CITY.
WHEN I'VE GONE BACK
IN THE MORNING,
THE CRATES ARE GONE.
HAND ME THAT?
ARCHER: THAT'S WHY YOU WERE
WATCHING HIS SHOP.
YOU THOUGHT WE WERE THERE
FOR THE CRATES.
WHAT IS THAT?
RIAAN: TEA.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOME?
T'POL: JON, MAY I
SPEAK WITH YOU?
I'D LOVE A CUP.
ARCHER: DID YOU GET
WHAT YOU NEED?
T'POL: MM-HMM.
I SHOULD RETURN TO THE SHIP
AND BEGIN MY ANALYSIS.
ARCHER: ALL RIGHT,
YOU AND THE OTHERS HEAD BACK.
T'POL: WHAT ABOUT YOU?
ARCHER: I'LL STAY HERE,
SEE IF I CAN LEARN MORE
ABOUT GAROS
AND THESE SHIPMENTS.
T'POL: THE LONGER YOU REMAIN,
THE MORE YOU RISK
CULTURAL CONTAMINATION.
ARCHER: THESE PEOPLE
ARE SUFFERING FROM
SOMETHING A LOT WORSE
THAN CULTURAL CONTAMINATION.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS.
T'POL: ENJOY YOUR TEA.
PHLOX: QUITE IMPRESSIVE.
DID YOU SAY THIS IS
A PREINDUSTRIAL SOCIETY?
T'POL: YES.
PHLOX: HMM.
HER METHODS MAY BE UNREFINED,
BUT THIS WOMAN IS USING
FORENSIC TECHNIQUES
FAR MORE SOPHISTICATED
THAN I WOULD HAVE EXPECTED.
ISN'T IT EXTRAORDINARY?
THOUSANDS OF SENTIENT SPECIES
IN OUR LITTLE CORNER
OF THE COSMOS,
EACH ONE DISCOVERING SCIENCE
IN THEIR OWN UNIQUE WAY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HAD THIS WOMAN BEEN BORN
ON VULCAN OR EARTH,
I'M SURE SHE WOULD HAVE
MADE A FINE PHYSICIAN.
AH.
AH, HERE'S OUR CULPRIT.
THE WATER SAMPLE'S CONTAMINATED
WITH TETRACYANATE 622.
T'POL: I'M NOT
FAMILIAR WITH IT.
PHLOX: IT'S
A SYNTHETIC COMPOUND,
PRIMARILY USED AS
AN INDUSTRIAL LUBRICANT,
USUALLY UNDER THE STRICTEST
SAFETY PROTOCOLS.
IT'S QUITE TOXIC.
T'POL: COULD THIS BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE EPIDEMIC?
PHLOX: IF IT'S MANAGED
TO SEEP INTO THE GROUNDWATER,
ABSOLUTELY.
T'POL: I'LL NOTIFY THE CAPTAIN.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
RIAAN: SAMPLES FROM
3 NEW SUBJECTS INDICATE NO...
ARCHER: DID YOU SAY SOMETHING?
RIAAN: SORRY.
I MUTTER WHAT I'M
WRITING SOMETIMES.
IT'S AN OLD HABIT.
ARCHER: I HAVE A SIMILAR ONE.
I TALK TO MY DOG.
[ RIAAN CHUCKLES ]
MY MOTHER BOUGHT ME A
[SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE] ONCE,
BUT IT [SPEAKS NATIVE LANGUAGE]
ARCHER: WHAT WAS THAT?
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
ARCHER: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
RIAAN: ALL RIGHT?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
ARCHER: SOMEONE WAS
WALKING THIS WAY,
BUT HE TURNED
AND WENT AROUND THE CORNER.
I THOUGHT
IF WE PRETENDED TO BE--
RIAAN: I UNDERSTAND.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ CONVERSATION
IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
ARCHER: I WANT YOU
TO HEAD BACK.
RIAAN: NOT BEFORE I SEE
WHAT'S IN THOSE CRATES.
HELP ME OPEN THIS.
ARCHER: MOVE!
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
ARCHER: ACTUALLY...I HAVE.
[ RIAAN GASPS ]
ARCHER: STAY HERE.
JON!
[ GASPS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ ARCHER GRUNTS ]
ALIEN: UGH!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'S NOT DEAD.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
YOU'D LIKE TO TELL ME, JON?
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
RIAAN: IF YOUR SHIP CAN TRAVEL
TO SO MANY STARS,
THEN WHY WOULD YOU COME HERE?
TO MEET YOU.
RIAAN: ME?
ARCHER: NOT YOU PERSONALLY,
BUT YOUR PEOPLE.
RIAAN: WHY?
WE'RE SO BACKWARD,
COMPARED TO YOU.
ARCHER: IF YOU TAKE AWAY
OUR TECHNOLOGY,
WE'RE NOT THAT DIFFERENT.
ARCHER: COME ON.
[ BEEPING ]
[ WHIRRING ]
ARCHER: THEY'RE MINING
SOME KIND OF VERIDIUM ISOTOPE.
T'POL: VERIDIUM IS PRIMARILY
USED TO MANUFACTURE EXPLOSIVES.
ARCHER: I'M NOT SURPRISED.
T'POL: DID YOU FIND ANY TRACES
OF TETRACYANATE?
ARCHER: THEIR DRILL BITS
ARE SATURATED WITH IT.
WE'VE GOT TO SHUT
THIS ALL DOWN.
THE REACTOR SEEMS TO BE POWERING
THE ENTIRE OPERATION,
BUT I CAN'T USE
MY PHASE PISTOL.
I'D RISK BLOWING UP
HALF THE CITY.
CAPTAIN, LET ME COME DOWN THERE
AND TAKE A CRACK AT IT.
ARCHER: I DOUBT THAT
WE HAVE THAT MUCH TIME.
OUR BEST SHOT IS
THE TRANSPORTER.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO
ABOUT DISENGAGING
THAT DAMPENING FIELD.
GIVE ME A FEW MINUTES.
T'POL: UNDERSTOOD.
ARCHER: I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU READ MALURIAN.
RIAAN: CAN'T YOU USE
YOUR DEVICE?
ARCHER: IT WASN'T
DESIGNED FOR THAT.
RIAAN: WHAT ARE WE LOOKING FOR?
ARCHER: THERE'S AN ENERGY FIELD
SURROUNDING THE SHOP.
IT'S KEEPING MY SHIP
FROM SEEING WHAT'S IN HERE.
ONE OF THESE CONTROLS
SHOULD TURN IT OFF.
RIAAN: HERE.
ARCHER: WHAT?
RIAAN: THIS IS TENGALA STREET.
HERE'S THE SHOP.
THIS OUTLINE COULD HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE ENERGY FIELD.
RIAAN: WAIT!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
ARCHER: IF THE BLUE LINE
REPRESENTS THE DAMPENING FIELD,
THIS BLUE BUTTON
SHOULD CONTROL IT.
RIAAN: WHAT ABOUT
THE YELLOW DOTS?
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT THEM?
RIAAN: HOW DO WE KNOW
THEY DON'T REPRESENT THE FIELD?
MAYBE IT'S THE YELLOW BUTTON.
ARCHER: NO, THE BLUE ONE'S LIT.
RIAAN: THAT'S WHAT WORRIES ME.
ARCHER: WE COULD
DEBATE THIS ALL DAY.
BLUE OR YELLOW?
RIAAN: BLUE.
[ ALARM BLARES ]
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
TRAVIS: THERE'S
A SHIP APPROACHING.
T'POL: FROM WHERE?
TRAVIS: IT MUST HAVE BEEN
IN A GEOSYNCHRONOUS ORBIT
ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE PLANET.
REED: I'M PICKING UP
MULTIPLE WEAPON PLATFORMS.
THEY'RE ARMED TO THE TEETH.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
HOSHI: WE'RE BEING HAILED
FROM THE SURFACE.
T'POL: THE CAPTAIN?
HOSHI: I DON'T THINK SO.
T'POL: ON SCREEN.
I SUGGEST YOU LEAVE
THIS SYSTEM AT ONCE,
OR MY SHIP WILL OPEN FIRE.
T'POL: I WANT TO SPEAK
WITH CAPTAIN ARCHER.
THAT WON'T BE POSSIBLE.
HE'S DEAD.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THE SHIP'S FIRING!
GAROS: MY VESSEL IS CAPABLE
OF FIRING 10 OF THOSE CHARGES
SIMULTANEOUSLY.
AGAIN, I SUGGEST
YOU BREAK ORBIT.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
GAROS: HOW DID YOU LEARN ABOUT
THIS FACILITY, CAPTAIN?
WAS IT FROM A SOMEWHAT UGLY
TELLARITE MERCHANT, PERHAPS?
ARCHER: I TOLD YOU.
WE DETECTED YOUR REACTOR
FROM ORBIT.
I FORGOT. YOU'RE EXPLORERS.
WE'RE TRYING TO HELP
THESE PEOPLE.
WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE
IS CONTAMINATING
THEIR WATER SUPPLY.
THERE ARE 500 MILLION AKAALI
ON THIS PLANET.
A FEW THOUSAND WON'T BE MISSED.
I'M WILLING TO LET YOU GO,
PROVIDED YOU PROMISE
NOT TO RETURN.
WE'VE INSTRUCTED YOUR SHIP
TO SEND DOWN A LAUNCH VEHICLE
TO TAKE YOU AND THE WOMAN.
SHE BELONGS HERE.
BELIEVE ME, SHE'LL BE
BETTER OFF ON YOUR SHIP.
NOW, STEP AWAY FROM
THE CONTROL PANEL, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: IF ANYONE WALKS THROUGH
EITHER OF THESE DOORS,
AIM THIS
AND PULL THE TRIGGER.
REED: THEY'RE
RECHARGING WEAPONS.
T'POL: PREPARE TO LEAVE ORBIT
ON MY ORDER.
TUCKER: BELAY THAT.
KEEP THIS SHIP
RIGHT WHERE IT IS.
T'POL: I DON'T HAVE TO REITERATE
THAT I OUTRANK YOU, MR. TUCKER.
ENSIGN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
CREWMAN: ENGINEERING.
TUCKER: BILLY, STAND BY TO VENT
THE NACELLES ON MY ORDER.
BILLY: YES, SIR.
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
T'POL: I DIDN'T SAY
LEAVE ORBIT.
I SAID PREPARE TO LEAVE ORBIT.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF ABANDONING THE CAPTAIN,
DEAD OR ALIVE.
HOSHI: THE DAMPENING
FIELD'S DOWN.
TUCKER: ANYTHING?
I'VE GOT A FIX ON IT.
TUCKER: TRANSFER
THE COORDINATES.
[ EXPLOSION ]
REED: THE FORWARD HULL
PLATING'S DEPOLARIZING.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
KEEP US
WITHIN TRANSPORTER RANGE.
I'LL TRY.
RETURN FIRE.
THEY'VE GOT SOME KIND
OF ENERGY SHIELDING.
OUR WEAPONS ARE INEFFECTIVE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
IT'S THE CAPTAIN.
PUT HIM THROUGH.
ARCHER: HOW'S IT GOING
UP THERE?
T'POL: A MALURIAN VESSEL'S
OPENED FIRE.
WE'RE TAKING DAMAGE.
ARCHER: AND THE REACTOR?
T'POL: WE'RE TRYING TO GET
A LOCK ON IT NOW.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
HE SAID YOU'D BEEN KILLED.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
JUST GET THE REACTOR.
RIAAN: JON.
TRAVIS: WE'VE LOST
LATERAL THRUSTERS.
COMMANDER TUCKER, STATUS?
THIS WOULD BE A LOT EASIER
IF YOU'D STOP ROCKING THE BOAT.
T'POL: HOW LONG?
I'VE ALMOST GOT A LOCK.
TRAVIS: I CAN'T SHAKE THEM.
EVEN IF WE GET THE REACTOR,
HOW ARE WE GONNA KEEP THEM
FROM TAKING IT BACK?
IF THEY WANT IT SO BADLY,
PERHAPS WE SHOULD
GIVE IT TO THEM.
[ CROWD GASPS,
INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
UGH!
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
I'VE GOT A LOCK.
STARBOARD TUBE'S LOADED.
T'POL: STAND BY TO GO
TO FULL IMPULSE.
NOW, COMMANDER.
FIRE.
THEIR SHIELDING IS DOWN.
COME ABOUT, ENSIGN.
TARGET THEIR WEAPONS ARRAY.
RIAAN: THE OIL LAMP.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT IT?
RIAAN: THERE SHOULD BE
AT LEAST A LITER
OF RESIDIC OIL
IN THE CONTAINER BELOW IT.
RESIDIC OIL IGNITES
AT 398 DEGREES.
YOU WOULDN'T HAPPEN TO HAVE
ANYTHING THAT GETS THAT HOT?
MAN: UGH!
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER.
T'POL: THE REACTOR'S
BEEN DESTROYED, CAPTAIN,
AND WE'VE DISARMED
THE MALURIAN SHIP.
SHOULD WE DISABLE
THEIR ENGINES?
ARCHER: NO. THEY'RE
ABOUT TO LEAVE.
BUT FIRST, THEY NEED TO
PICK UP 3 PASSENGERS.
ARCHER OUT.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TIME TO PACK UP YOUR SHOP.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
JULY 31, 2151.
WE'VE REMOVED
THE MINING EQUIPMENT
FROM UNDER THE SHOP.
AS FAR AS WE CAN TELL,
NONE OF THE AKAALI KNOWS
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED,
WITH ONE EXCEPTION.
ARCHER: TELL THEM TO TAKE
THE ENTIRE DOSE.
RIAAN: JUST ONE?
ARCHER: THAT'S
ALL THEY'LL NEED.
RIAAN: WHAT IF GAROS
COMES BACK?
ARCHER: I'VE NOTIFIED
T'POL'S PEOPLE.
THEY'RE GOING TO LOOK IN ON YOU
FROM TIME TO TIME.
RIAAN: THEY COULD
STOP BY FOR TEA.
ARCHER: YOU BET.
IT'S PROBABLY BEST IF YOU...
KEEP ALL THIS TO YOURSELF.
RIAAN: WHO'D BELIEVE ME ANYWAY?
WHERE IS YOUR STARSHIP
HEADED NOW?
THERE ARE LOTS OF
INHABITED PLANETS TO SEE.
BUT I DOUBT MANY WILL
BE THIS MEMORABLE.
RIAAN: IS YOUR TRANSLATOR
BROKEN AGAIN?
I'M SORRY. I DON'T UNDERSTAND
A WORD YOU'RE SAYING.