THIS WASN'T PART
OF OUR AGREEMENT.
FUTURE MAN:
YOU FAILED IN YOUR LAST MISSION.
THE KLINGON EMPIRE IS INTACT.
YOU KNEW THERE
WOULD BE CONSEQUENCES.
SILIK: PLEASE, I WON'T
DISAPPOINT YOU AGAIN.
FUTURE MAN:
WE WILL RESTORE IT,
BUT ONLY IF YOU SUCCEED
IN YOUR NEXT MISSION.
BUT...YOU'RE DISABLING ME.
FUTURE MAN: YOU WON'T NEED
ENHANCED VISION
WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
PROCEED WITH THE EXTRACTION.
[ WHIRRING ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
TRAVIS: HOLD THE DOOR.
HEY.
WHERE WERE YOU LAST NIGHT?
I DECIDED
TO TURN IN EARLY.
TRAVIS: WELL,
YOU DIDN'T MISS MUCH.
WHAT'D THEY SHOW?
"NIGHT OF THE KILLER ANDROIDS."
THAT BAD?
TRAVIS:
WE'VE GOT 50,000 MOVIES
IN THE DATABASE.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING
WORTH WATCHING.
YOU COULD ALWAYS
READ A BOOK.
TRAVIS: LIEUTENANT.
REED: ENSIGNS.
ENJOY THE SHOW LAST NIGHT?
UGH.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THOSE WERE TWO HOURS OF MY LIFE
I'D RATHER HAVE BACK.
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
MORNING, DANIELS.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS
TAYLOR'S SHIFT.
DANIELS: I SWITCHED WITH HIM,
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT WITH YOU.
ARCHER: NO PROBLEM.
SIR, I NOTICED
WE CHANGED COURSE.
DANIELS: MAY I ASK WHY?
THERE'S A STELLAR NURSERY
NOT FAR FROM HERE.
WE DETECTED
SEVERAL SHIPS INSIDE.
WE THOUGHT WE MIGHT
GO SAY HELLO.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
MORE ORANGE JUICE?
ARCHER: NO, THANKS,
I'M FINE.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
WE FOUND ONE OF THE SHIPS, SIR.
PUT IT UP.
T'POL: IT APPEARS TO BE
A TRANSPORT VESSEL.
HAIL THEM.
THEY'RE RESPONDING.
CAN I HELP YOU?
MY NAME IS ARCHER.
I'M CAPTAIN
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
WE ARE FROM EARTH.
WE THOUGHT
WE'D INTRODUCE OURSELVES.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
NOTHING.
WE'RE NEW TO THIS REGION,
AND WE'RE EAGER TO MAKE CONTACT
WITH OTHER SPECIES.
OH.
IF YOU DON'T MIND MY ASKING...
WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE?
A JOB.
I'M ESCORTING A GROUP
OF SPIRITUALLY MINDED MEN
ON A PILGRIMAGE
TO THE GREAT PLUME OF AGOSORIA.
THE -- THE WHAT?
EVERY 11 YEARS,
ONE OF THE PROTOSTARS
GIVES OUT A NEUTRON BLAST.
THESE GENTLEMEN BELIEVE
IT'S A SACRED EVENT.
IF YOU ASK ME, I THINK IT'S
JUST ANOTHER BALL OF HYDROGEN.
T'POL: WHEN IS
THIS GREAT PLUME DUE TO ERUPT?
TOMORROW.
MIND IF WE JOIN YOU?
IT'S YOUR TIME TO WASTE.
I'D LIKE TO EXTEND AN INVITATION
TO YOU AND YOUR PASSENGERS
TO VISIT ENTERPRISE.
I'LL ASK THEM
IF THEY'RE INTERESTED.
I PREFER TO STAY WITH MY SHIP.
UNDERSTOOD, MISTER...?
FRADDOCK. CAPTAIN FRADDOCK.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
LOOKS LIKE
WE COULD BE HAVING GUESTS.
TELL CHEF TO PREPARE...
SOMETHING.
[ BEEP ]
SEAL'S GOOD.
ARCHER: WELCOME ABOARD.
CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
IT'S CUSTOMARY ON EARTH
TO GREET SOMEONE
WITH A HANDSHAKE.
I'M PRAH MANTOOS.
MAY AGOSORIA EMBRACE YOU
INTO HIS CYCLE OF RENEWAL.
THANKS.
THESE ARE MY FELLOW CELEBRANTS.
WE'VE TRAVELED MANY LIGHT-YEARS
FROM DIFFERENT WORLDS
TO...WATCH THIS EVENT.
I'M COMMANDER TUCKER,
CHIEF ENGINEER,
AND THIS IS OUR SCIENCE
OFFICER, SUBCOMMANDER T'POL.
FOR YOU, CAPTAIN.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WHAT, UH, EXACTLY IS IT?
MANTOOS: A CLOCK.
IT CHARTS TIME FROM
THE BEGINNING OF THE UNIVERSE.
VOO-SINTEEL.
IT'S A SPIRIT
TRADITIONALLY CONSUMED
AS THE PLUME REACHES
ITS FULL BRILLIANCE.
YOU'LL FIND IT ENHANCES
THE EXPERIENCE.
MMM, I'M SURE IT DOES.
YOU'RE VERY GENEROUS.
I'M...AFRAID THE ONLY THING
WE HAVE TO OFFER YOU
IS OUR HOSPITALITY.
THAT WILL BE MORE THAN ENOUGH.
ARCHER: OUR CHEF HAS PREPARED
A MEAL IN YOUR HONOR.
NORMALLY WE FAST DURING
THE TIME OF AGOSORIA,
BUT IN THIS CASE, I SUPPOSE
WE CAN...BREAK WITH TRADITION.
PLEASE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ARCHER: FOUR MONTHS,
THREE WEEKS, AND...
T'POL: SIX DAYS.
MANTOOS: YOU'VE TRAVELED
A GREAT DISTANCE
IN A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
TUCKER: WARP 5 WILL GET YOU
WHERE YOU'RE GOING PRETTY FAST.
WE'VE, UH, SEEN A LOT
SINCE WE LEFT EARTH,
BUT I HAVE TO SAY
THAT THIS PLACE
IS DEFINITELY ONE
OF THE HIGHLIGHTS.
I'M PLEASED YOU APPRECIATE
ITS BEAUTY, CAPTAIN.
TO US, IT'S MORE THAN JUST
A SIMPLE STELLAR NURSERY.
ACCORDING TO OUR SACRED TEXTS,
THIS IS WHERE
THE UNIVERSE BEGAN.
TUCKER: AND THE GREAT PLUME
OF A-- AGO--
AGOSORIA.
HOW DOES THAT FIT IN?
IT REPRESENTS THE CONTINUING
CYCLE OF CREATION.
MMM. IT'S NOT UNLIKE
THE HINDU FAITH, COMMANDER.
THEY ALSO BELIEVE THAT
THE UNIVERSE GOES
THROUGH REPEATED CYCLES
OF REBIRTH.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU WERE FAMILIAR
WITH EARTH RELIGIONS, DOCTOR.
PHLOX: OH, YES.
IN FACT, WHILE I WAS THERE,
I MADE IT A POINT
TO STUDY A NUMBER OF THEM.
I SPENT TWO WEEKS
AT A TIBETAN MONASTERY,
WHERE I LEARNED TO SING CHORDS
WITH THE HIGH LAMAS.
I ATTENDED MASS
AT SAINT PETER'S SQUARE.
I WAS EVEN ALLOWED
TO OBSERVE THE TAL-SHANAR
AT THE VULCAN CONSULATE.
I UNDERSTAND VULCANS ARE
A DEEPLY SPIRITUAL PEOPLE.
OUR BELIEFS ARE BASED ON LOGIC
AND THE PURSUIT OF CLARITY.
DO YOU FOLLOW A PARTICULAR
FAITH, CAPTAIN?
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY I...
TRY TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND.
MANY WHO SEE THE GREAT PLUME
ARE OFTEN INSPIRED BY IT.
PERHAPS YOU WILL BE, TOO.
ARCHER: MMM.
DID YOU GET TO MEET THEM?
TWO. BRIEFLY.
WHAT WERE THEY LIKE?
HOSHI: UH...QUIET.
THEY'RE TAKING A TOUR
OF THE SHIP.
LOOKS LIKE THE CAPTAIN'S
GOING ALL OUT.
I HOPE HE'S NOT PLANNING
TO SHOW THEM THE ARMORY.
HOSHI: DON'T WORRY,
LIEUTENANT.
THEY DIDN'T LOOK
LIKE THE TYPES WHO'D
GO AROUND STEALING
MILITARY SECRETS.
REED: STILL, WE'RE NOT
FAMILIAR WITH THESE SPECIES.
TACTICAL SYSTEMS
SHOULD BE OFF-LIMITS.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
THE STARBOARD TARGETING
SENSOR'S OUT AGAIN.
HOSHI: SHOULD I CALL
ENGINEERING?
REED: NO, I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
IT'LL ONLY TAKE A MOMENT.
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE, ENSIGN.
AREN'T YOU GOING
TO TAKE THE CHAIR?
WHAT?
YOU'RE IN COMMAND.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'M FINE RIGHT HERE.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER WONDERED
WHAT IT'S LIKE?
I CAN WAIT TILL I'M PROMOTED.
OKAY.
NICE FIT.
BRIDGE LOOKS A LOT
DIFFERENT FROM HERE.
THINK ANYONE WOULD MIND
IF I FIRED A TORPEDO?
PERMISSION TO TAKE MY STATION?
SORRY, SIR.
TUCKER: THE GRAVIMETRIC FIELD
DISPLACEMENT MANIFOLD --
COMMONLY KNOWN
AS THE WARP REACTOR.
JUST THINK OF IT
AS A GREAT BIG ENGINE,
BUT INSTEAD OF USING
ELECTRICITY OR CHEMICAL FUEL,
IT RUNS ON ANTIMATTER.
SEE THIS SWIRLING LIGHT?
WHEN MATTER AND ANTIMATTER
COLLIDE,
IT CREATES A WHOLE LOT
OF ENERGY, AND WE CHANNEL
THAT ENERGY THROUGH
THOSE CONDUITS OVER THERE.
THEY LEAD TO THE TWO
LARGE, GLOWING CYLINDERS
YOU MAY HAVE SEEN
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THE SHIP.
-THE NACELLES.
-THAT'S RIGHT.
SONSORRA: WHICH CONTAIN
WARP COILS THAT CREATE
THE SUBSPACE
DISPLACEMENT FIELD.
I SEE YOU...ALREADY KNOW A THING
OR TWO ABOUT STARSHIP ENGINES.
I'M A WARP FIELD THEORIST.
OH.
WELL...
I GUESS THAT COVERS THE BASICS.
ANY QUESTIONS?
ALIEN: HOW DO YOU
REGULATE POSITRON FLOW
IN YOUR DILITHIUM MATRIX?
GOOD ONE.
I'LL BRING UP THE SCHEMATIC
OF THE REACTOR ASSEMBLY.
YOU CAN SEE FOR YOURSELF.
IF YOU'LL JUST COME WITH ME.
TUCKER: WE USE A SERIES
OF MAGNETIC CONSTRICTORS
TO ALIGN THE POSITRON STREAM.
IF ANY STRAY PARTICLES ESCAPE,
BACKUPS AUTOMATICALLY KICK IN.
DURING ONE
OF OUR TRAINING TESTS,
WE MOMENTARILY LOST
THE PRIMARIES AND THE BACKUPS.
ABOUT A BILLION POSITRONS
CUT THROUGH THE PLATING
ON THREE DECKS.
NEARLY CAUSED A HULL BREACH.
WE SPENT A MONTH
REDESIGNING THE SYSTEM.
IT HASN'T GIVEN US
A SINGLE PROBLEM SINCE.
[ CONSOLE BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED
BY CAPTAIN FRADDOCK.
TRAVIS: HE'S PROBABLY CALLING
ABOUT THE WEATHER.
T'POL: ON SCREEN.
FRADDOCK: YOU MIGHT WANT
TO FOCUS YOUR SENSORS
ON THAT PLASMA LIGHTNING
UP AHEAD.
WE'RE AWARE OF IT.
FRADDOCK: YOU EVER BEEN
IN A PLASMA STORM?
-TWICE.
-THEN YOU KNOW
IT CAN GET A LITTLE BUMPY.
I SUGGEST WE TRY
AND GO AROUND IT.
AGREED.
ENSIGN.
I'M ALREADY ON IT.
PHLOX: THERE'S YOUR HEART,
LUNGS, LIVER...
ANOTHER HEART. HEH!
EVERY ORGAN.
THIS IMAGING DEVICE
ALSO ALLOWS US
TO EXAMINE
YOUR GENETIC STRUCTURE.
AH. YOU'LL BE HAPPY TO KNOW
YOU'RE IN PERFECT HEALTH.
WHO WOULD LIKE TO GO NEXT?
[ DEEP RUMBLING ]
EXCUSE ME.
ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
REPORT.
WE'RE CIRCUMNAVIGATING
A PLASMA STORM, CAPTAIN.
T'POL: IT'S JUST TURBULENCE
FROM THE OUTER EDGE.
THEY'RE VERY COMMON
IN THIS REGION.
I'M SURE THERE'S NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
THAT ONE HIT OUR PORT BOW.
POWER'S DOWN ON C-DECK,
SUBSECTION 4.
NO OTHER DAMAGE.
ENSIGN.
THE STORM'S MOVING
IN OUR DIRECTION.
I'M HAVING TROUBLE
GETTING AROUND IT.
WHAT ABOUT THE TRANSPORT SHIP?
HE'S FAR ENOUGH AHEAD.
HE MADE IT PAST.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
TUCKER: WE'VE GOT A POWER SURGE
IN THE IMPULSE RELAYS.
HERE'S A GOOD EXAMPLE OF HOW
WE CAN REROUTE THE ENERGY FLOW
TO PROTECT OUR CRITICAL SYSTEMS.
I'M AFRAID WE HAVE TO CUT
THE TOUR A LITTLE SHORT.
I'LL BE ON THE BRIDGE.
REPORT.
REED: WE'RE LOSING MAIN POWER.
TRIP, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
THAT LAST BOLT STRUCK
THE WARP MANIFOLD.
We've got
an antimatter cascade, sir.
IF IT REACHES THE WARP REACTOR,
WE'RE GONNA --
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
I THINK WE'RE ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN.
THE CASCADE STOPPED
IN ITS TRACKS.
GOOD WORK, TRIP.
IT WASN'T ME, SIR.
ARCHER: SORRY ABOUT
THE BAD WEATHER.
WE'RE USED TO IT.
I'M JUST GRATEFUL
THERE WAS NO SERIOUS DAMAGE.
IF ANY OF YOUR GROUP
WOULD LIKE TO WATCH THE
GREAT PLUME FROM OUR MESS HALL,
THEY'RE WELCOME
TO COME BACK TOMORROW.
I'LL LET THEM KNOW.
HAVE A GREAT TIME, DOCTOR.
I PLAN TO, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU FOR LETTING ME SPEND
THE NIGHT WITH THESE PEOPLE.
I'LL EXPECT A FULL REPORT
IN THE MORNING.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
HOPE TO SEE YOU TOMORROW.
[ BEEP ]
Tucker to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD, TRIP.
Can you come down
to Engineering for a minute?
ON MY WAY.
WHAT IS IT, TRIP?
TUCKER: TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
WHAT?
RIGHT UP THERE.
SEE THAT CONDUIT?
YEAH.
IT'S AN ANTIMATTER JUNCTION.
IT STOPPED THE CASCADE
FROM REACHING THE WARP REACTOR.
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT?
SOMEBODY GOT IN HERE
AND DISCONNECTED IT
FROM THE PRIMARY
ANTIMATTER FEED.
IF THEY HADN'T, THAT CASCADE
WOULD HAVE CONTINUED
RIGHT INTO THE REACTOR CORE,
AND THIS SHIP WOULD HAVE GONE UP
JUST LIKE
THE GREAT PLUME OF AGOSORIA.
ONE OF YOUR STAFF?
I ALREADY ASKED.
NOBODY SEEMS TO KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
SOUNDS TO ME
LIKE YOU'VE GOT A HERO
WHO'S A LITTLE RELUCTANT
ABOUT TAKING CREDIT.
TALK TO THEM AGAIN.
WHOEVER DID THIS
DESERVES A COMMENDATION.
I'M TELLING YOU, SIR,
I DON'T THINK
IT WAS ONE OF MY PEOPLE.
THEY WOULD HAVE SAID SOMETHING.
FRADDOCK: I SPOKE
WITH EVERY ONE OF THEM.
-HOW ABOUT THE WARP THEORIST?
-HIM, TOO.
NONE OF THEM WENT ANYWHERE
NEAR THAT CONDUIT.
FRADDOCK: IF I TOLD YOU
I DID IT,
WOULD THERE BE
SOME KIND OF REWARD?
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
OH, WELL, MAYBE IT WAS
THE CYCLE OF RENEWAL.
IF ANYONE COMES FORWARD,
YOU'LL LET ME KNOW?
OH, YOU'LL BE THE FIRST.
[ SIGHS ]
SIR, I NEED TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
WHY DON'T YOU TALK
TO ONE OF MY BRIDGE OFFICERS?
I'M A LITTLE BUSY RIGHT NOW.
-IT'S IMPORTANT.
-I'M SORRY, DANIELS.
I'VE GOT MY HANDS FULL.
DANIELS: IT'S ABOUT
THE SULIBAN.
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
DANIELS: I HAVE
REASON TO BELIEVE
THAT ONE OF THE PILGRIMS
WHO CAME ABOARD TODAY
IS A SULIBAN SOLDIER.
HIS NAME IS SILIK.
HE'S THE MAN YOU FOUGHT WITH
ON THE HELIX.
HOW THE HELL DO YOU KNOW
WHAT I DID ON THE HELIX?
IT MIGHT BE BEST
IF WE DISCUSSED THIS
IN PRIVATE.
MY READY ROOM.
I THINK IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF WE WENT TO MY QUARTERS.
WHAT?
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND
WHEN WE GET THERE, SIR.
OH, PLEASE, HAVE A SEAT.
I'M SORRY ABOUT THE MESS.
SOMETIMES I THINK MY BUNK-MATE
MAJORED IN CHAOS THEORY.
WHAT IS THAT?
ARCHER: THAT DOESN'T LOOK
LIKE STARFLEET ISSUE.
DANIELS: IT'S BECAUSE I'M NOT
A MEMBER OF STARFLEET.
NOT THAT I WOULDN'T
BE HONORED TO BE ONE, SIR,
ESPECIALLY AFTER
SPENDING TIME--
WHO ARE YOU?
HOW DO YOU KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED ON THE HELIX?
DID SILIK TELL YOU WHO
HE WAS WORKING FOR?
ARCHER: I'M THE ONE ASKING
QUESTIONS, CREWMAN.
DID HE MENTION
THE TEMPORAL COLD WAR?
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
A GREAT DEAL MORE
THAN YOU DO, SIR.
IF YOU'RE NOT A MEMBER
OF STARFLEET,
THEN WHO ARE YOU?
I WORK FOR A DIFFERENT KIND
OF ORGANIZATION.
WE MAKE SURE THAT PEOPLE
LIKE SILIK DON'T
INTERFERE WITH
HISTORICAL EVENTS.
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF
A GROUP LIKE THAT.
THAT'S BECAUSE
IT DOESN'T EXIST YET.
SO YOU'RE...TELLING ME
YOU'RE SOME KIND
OF A TIME TRAVELER?
THAT'S ONE WAY OF PUTTING IT.
MAYBE THIS WILL HELP
CLEAR THINGS UP.
THIS IS HOW WE KEEP AN EYE
ON WHAT'S GOING ON.
YOU MIGHT CALL IT
A TEMPORAL OBSERVATORY.
I KNOW THIS MUST SEEM
A LITTLE OVERWHELMING.
OVERWHELMING...
DOESN'T QUITE COVER IT.
I COME FROM RIGHT ABOUT,
UH...RIGHT ABOUT HERE,
APPROXIMATELY 900 YEARS
FROM NOW.
ARE YOU HUMAN?
MORE OR LESS.
AND THE PEOPLE GIVING
SILIK ORDERS?
THEY'RE FROM AN EARLIER CENTURY,
FROM ABOUT...HERE.
THEY CAN'T MANIFEST THEMSELVES
PHYSICALLY IN THE PAST.
THEY CAN ONLY
PARTIALLY MATERIALIZE
TO DELIVER INFORMATION.
-BUT NOT YOU?
-IN THE YEARS THAT FOLLOWED,
WE EVENTUALLY PERFECTED
THE PROCESS.
SOUNDS DANGEROUS.
WHEN TIME TRAVEL WAS
FIRST DEVELOPED,
IT WASN'T LONG
BEFORE PEOPLE REALIZED
THAT LAWS HAD TO BE MADE.
ALL THE SPECIES WHO HAD
THE TECHNOLOGY AGREED
THAT IT WOULD ONLY
BE USED FOR RESEARCH.
BUT IT WASN'T.
THAT'S WHAT THE TEMPORAL
COLD WAR IS ALL ABOUT.
LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS A GROUP
OF ANTHROPOLOGISTS FROM 2769
OBSERVING THE CONSTRUCTION
OF THE GREAT PYRAMID AT GIZA.
THEY'RE DOING IT USING
THE PROPER PROCEDURES
SET FORTH
IN THE TEMPORAL ACCORD.
BUT THERE ARE FACTIONS
THAT IGNORE THOSE PROCEDURES.
WHY ARE YOU TELLING ME
ALL THIS?
SILIK IS THE ONE WHO
PREVENTED THE REACTOR BREACH.
ARE YOU IMPLYING SILIK WAS
SENT HERE TO SAVE MY SHIP?
AND IF HE HADN'T,
WE WOULD HAVE BEEN
DESTROYED TODAY?
I AM NOT IMPLYING ANYTHING.
ALL I'M SAYING IS THAT
I WAS ASSIGNED HERE
TO CAPTURE SILIK
WHEN HE CAME ABOARD.
HE IS A THREAT, AND I NEED YOU
TO HELP ME CAPTURE HIM.
YOU'RE FROM...
900 YEARS IN THE FUTURE,
AND YOU NEED MY HELP?
THE SULIBAN HAVE BEEN GIVEN
GENETIC ENHANCEMENTS
THAT ALLOW THEM
TO EVADE MOST SENSORS.
THEY'RE NEARLY
IMPOSSIBLE TO DETECT.
I'VE NOTICED.
I HAVE SPECIAL EQUIPMENT
THAT CAN HELP TRACK SILIK,
BUT IT'LL BE FAR MORE EFFECTIVE
IF I CAN TIE IT IN
TO YOUR INTERNAL SENSOR GRID.
I'LL NEED ACCESS
TO MAIN ENGINEERING
AND YOUR COMMAND CODES.
WE HAVE REASON TO BELIEVE
THAT THE 22nd CENTURY
IS A FRONT IN THIS COLD WAR.
WHAT HAPPENS HERE COULD AFFECT
MILLENNIA TO COME.
IT'S IMPERATIVE
THAT WE FIND OUT
WHO SILIK IS WORKING FOR
AND WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO DO.
IF I DECIDE TO HELP YOU,
I CAN'T DO IT ALONE.
I NEED TO INFORM
SOME OF MY CREW.
THE FEWER THE BETTER.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO CAPTURE SOMEONE
WHO JUST SAVED MY SHIP.
WHY SHOULD I TRUST YOU?
YOU LIKE
YOUR SCRAMBLED EGGS SOFT.
HAVE I EVER BROUGHT THEM
TO YOU ANY OTHER WAY?
YOU SURE
YOU DON'T WANT A GLASS?
I'M SURE.
THE VULCAN SCIENCE DIRECTORATE
HAS STUDIED THE QUESTION
OF TIME TRAVEL IN GREAT DETAIL.
THEY FOUND NO EVIDENCE
THAT IT EXISTS
OR THAT IT CAN EXIST.
THE SULIBAN WOMAN
I SPOKE WITH -- SARIN --
SHE ALSO USED THE PHRASE
"TEMPORAL COLD WAR."
-THAT'S WHAT DANIELS CALLED IT?
-THE SAME WORDS.
THAT PROVES NOTHING.
WHAT ABOUT THE SULIBAN'S
GENETIC ENGINEERING?
PHLOX SAYS IT'S FAR
BEYOND THEIR ABILITIES.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN
THAT IT WAS GIVEN TO THEM
BY VISITORS FROM THE FUTURE.
UNTIL DANIELS CAN OFFER YOU
CONCRETE PROOF,
I'D REMAIN EXTREMELY SKEPTICAL.
I'M TELLING YOU, HE PUSHED
A BUTTON ON THIS DEVICE
AND THE WHOLE ROOM CHANGED.
ON THE XYRILLIAN SHIP,
I WAS IN A HOLOGRAPHIC CHAMBER
WHERE I COULD'VE SWORN
I WAS IN A BOAT AT SEA.
IF WHAT DANIELS SAYS IS TRUE,
THEN SILIK SAVED ENTERPRISE.
MAYBE WE SHOULDN'T LOOK
A GIFT HORSE IN THE MOUTH.
IF THERE'S EVEN A POSSIBILITY
THAT THIS COLD WAR EXISTS,
WE CAN'T IGNORE
DANIELS' REQUEST.
Bridge to Captain Archer.
YES, HOSHI?
We're approaching
the protostar, sir, and
THE TRANSPORT SHIP IS REQUESTING
PERMISSION TO DOCK.
SOME OF THE PASSENGERS
WOULD LIKE TO TAKE YOU UP
ON YOUR OFFER AND OBSERVE IT
FROM THE MESS HALL.
INITIATE DOCKING PROCEDURES.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
ONE OF THEM MIGHT BE SILIK.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
TO DEBATE THIS ANY LONGER.
I WANT YOU TO HELP DANIELS.
I ALWAYS KNEW WE'D
BE MEETING PEOPLE
FROM OTHER PLANETS, BUT...
OTHER CENTURIES?
YOU'RE NOT BUYING ANY
OF THIS, ARE YOU?
IF DANIELS COULD TRAVEL
THROUGH TIME,
WHY NOT SIMPLY GO BACK ONE MORE
DAY INTO THE PAST AND PREVENT
SILIK FROM BOARDING THIS SHIP
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
MAYBE THAT'S PLAN "B."
OR MAYBE HE'S REALLY
NOT FROM THE FUTURE.
THEN WHY MAKE UP SUCH
A CRAZY STORY?
HE COULD BE TRYING TO CONCEAL
HIS TRUE INTENTIONS.
I THOUGHT YOU SCIENTISTS
WERE SUPPOSED
TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND.
THERE'S A DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN KEEPING AN OPEN MIND
AND BELIEVING SOMETHING
BECAUSE YOU WANT IT TO BE TRUE.
WHAT THE HELL'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
[ PHLOX SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE ] ...CAPTAIN.
THAT IS A TRADITIONAL GREETING
ON THE MORNING OF AGOSORIA.
IT MEANS, "MAY THE PLUME
LIGHT YOUR WAY." HEH HEH!
TAKE IT
YOU ENJOYED YOUR VISIT.
OH, IT WAS MESMERIZING.
FOUR HOURS OF RITUAL PRAYER,
FOLLOWED BY THE KAANA-SAH,
A SERIES OF EXERCISES
DESIGNED TO PURIFY
THE BODY. HEH HEH!
I THINK I STRAINED A LEG MUSCLE,
BUT IT WAS WELL WORTH IT.
HOW MANY DECIDED TO JOIN US?
11, I BELIEVE;
THE OTHERS WANTED
TO OBSERVE THE STAR
FROM THEIR SHIP.
SO THAT LEAVES...
SIX ON THE TRANSPORT?
I DIDN'T TAKE A HEAD COUNT,
BUT THAT SOUNDS ABOUT RIGHT.
DID ANY OF THEM SEEM
OUT OF PLACE?
HOW DO YOU MEAN?
DID THEY ALL TAKE PART
IN THE RITUALS?
AS FAR AS I COULD TELL,
BUT OUR EYES WERE CLOSED
MOST OF THE TIME.
IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG,
CAPTAIN?
[ OVERLAPPING CHATTER ]
NO. JUST CURIOUS.
YOU SEEM A LITTLE PREOCCUPIED.
IT'S BEEN A LONG NIGHT.
I'M GLAD YOU HAD A GOOD TIME.
ENJOY THE VIEW.
I WILL.
MY EQUIPMENT DRAWS
A LOT OF POWER.
I'LL NEED ANOTHER 20 MEGAWATTS
ROUTED TO YOUR SENSOR GRID.
COMMANDER.
THE GRID CAN HANDLE IT.
SO I TAKE IT
YOUR BROTHER ISN'T REALLY
AN ORBITAL ENGINEER
AT JUPITER STATION.
DANIELS: ACTUALLY,
I DON'T HAVE A BROTHER.
TUCKER: AND YOU DIDN'T
GROW UP IN ILLINOIS.
OH, I'M FROM A PLACE
CALLED ILLINOIS, SIR --
JUST NOT THE ONE
YOU'RE FAMILIAR WITH.
TUCKER: IT'S GOOD TO KNOW EARTH
WILL STILL BE AROUND
IN 900 YEARS.
THAT DEPENDS ON HOW
YOU DEFINE EARTH.
BEG YOUR PARDON?
DANIELS: YOU MIGHT WANT
TO INITIALIZE THE GRID.
I'M READY TO DOWNLOAD
THE BIOMETRIC PARAMETERS.
RIGHT.
WHAT'S THIS?
THAT'S VERY DELICATE.
PLEASE DON'T --
PLEASE DON'T TOUCH IT.
YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT A LITTLE
POOL GOING IN ENGINEERING
WHERE WE TRY TO GUESS HOW FAR
THE SHIP WILL TRAVEL EACH DAY.
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU COULD GIVE
ME A TIP ON TOMORROW'S DISTANCE.
[ CHUCKLES ] I'M AFRAID
WE DON'T MONITOR EVENTS
QUITE THAT CLOSELY.
ONE OF THE POWER RELAYS
IS OFF-LINE.
MUST HAVE BEEN DAMAGED
DURING THE PLASMA STORM.
J-37. IT'S ABOUT 3 METERS
BEHIND THAT BULKHEAD.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
J-37?
TRY IT NOW.
[ BARKING ]
I KNOW, I KNOW, YOUR BREAKFAST
IS TWO HOURS LATE.
DON'T GIVE ME THAT LOOK.
IF IT'S ANY CONSOLATION,
I MISSED MY BREAKFAST, TOO.
[ BARKING ]
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
[ BARKS ]
YOU'RE NOT GETTING ANY CHEESE.
[ GROWLS ]
[ PORTHOS GROWLING ]
SILIK: IF YOU'RE THINKING
OF CALLING FOR HELP,
I'D ADVISE AGAINST IT.
I'M NOT THE ONE YOU SHOULD BE
WORRIED ABOUT, JON.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
SILIK: I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
WANT TO THANK ME.
I SAVED YOUR LIFE.
THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
IS RETURN THE FAVOR.
THERE'S SOMEONE HERE
TRYING TO FIND ME.
I NEED TO KNOW WHO IT IS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
I DETECT A TACHYON RADIATION.
YOU DON'T HAVE ANYTHING
THAT EMITS TACHYONS.
WHO'S LOOKING FOR ME?
I DON'T KNOW.
DID THEY TELL YOU
THAT RIDICULOUS STORY
ABOUT THEIR NOBLE EFFORTS
TO PROTECT HISTORY?
THE GREAT TEMPORAL ACCORD?
THEY'RE LYING TO YOU, JON.
NONE OF IT IS TRUE.
WHOEVER CONTACTED YOU
IS WORKING FOR ANOTHER FACTION.
THEY DIDN'T COME HERE
TO PROTECT HISTORY.
THEY CAME TO ALTER IT.
WHO DO YOU THINK
WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE ANTIMATTER CASCADE
THAT NEARLY DESTROYED YOUR SHIP?
IT WAS THEM.
I WAS SENT TO PREVENT IT.
AND WHY WOULD YOU
WANT TO DO THAT?
THE FIRST TIME WE MET,
YOU TRIED TO KILL ME.
I SAVED YOUR SHIP BECAUSE I
WAS INSTRUCTED TO.
ARCHER: BY WHOM?
WHAT DOES ENTERPRISE
HAVE TO DO
WITH YOUR TEMPORAL WAR?
I'M NOT PRIVY
TO THAT KIND OF INFORMATION,
BUT I CAN TELL YOU THIS --
WHOEVER'S LOOKING FOR ME
IS A DANGER TO YOUR CREW.
IF YOU WANT TO CONTINUE
ON YOUR MISSION,
YOU'LL HELP ME FIND THEM.
[ BEEP ]
T'Pol to Captain Archer.
ARCHER HERE.
We've finished
the modifications.
THANKS.
I'LL BE THERE IN A FEW MINUTES.
Mr. Daniels is eager
to get started.
HE'LL HAVE TO WAIT
A FEW MINUTES. ARCHER OUT.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY HELPFUL, JON.
[ PORTHOS BARKING ]
[ PORTHOS WHINES ]
IT'S BEGINNING.
HOW LONG BEFORE
WE SEE THE PLUME?
NOW, THAT'S HARD TO PREDICT.
EVERY CYCLE IS UNIQUE.
WOULD YOU CARE TO RECITE THE
INVOCATION OF RENEWAL WITH US?
I'D BE HONORED.
[ SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]--
[ SPEAKS FOREIGN WORD ]
[ REPEATS WORD ]
[ CONTINUES SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
[ ALL SPEAKING
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
[ ALL REPEATING ]
TUCKER: DOES THIS MEAN
IT'S WORKING?
DANIELS: IT'S WORKING.
[ BEEPING ]
-WHAT IS IT?
-SULIBAN BIO-SIGNS.
HE'S SOMEWHERE ON THIS DECK.
I CAN'T ISOLATE HIM,
BUT HE'S CLOSE.
CALL LIEUTENANT REED.
TELL HIM TO SEAL OFF C-DECK.
AND IT WOULDN'T HURT
IF HE COULD GET DOWN HERE
WITH A SECURITY TEAM.
WHAT'S THAT?
YOU TWO SHOULD GO.
-WE'RE NOT LEAVING.
-GO!
BRING HELP. GO.
TUCKER: EVACUATE ENGINEERING.
EVERYBODY OUT!
DID THEY TELL YOU THAT
THE 22nd CENTURY WAS
GOING TO BE YOUR FINAL
RESTING PLACE?
[ GROANS ]
STILL SKEPTICAL?
TUCKER TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
CAPTAIN, YOU THERE?
T'POL: HE'S IN HIS QUARTERS.
-TUCKER TO DR. PHLOX.
-Yes, Commander?
MEET US IN THE CAPTAIN'S
QUARTERS ON THE DOUBLE.
On my way.
[ GROANS ]
EASY, CAPTAIN.
ASIDE FROM A NASTY HEADACHE,
YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
YOU WERE STUNNED
BY A PARTICLE WEAPON.
IT WAS SILIK.
I GUESS HE DECIDED NOT TO TRY
AND KILL ME THIS TIME.
HE WASN'T QUITE AS GENEROUS
WHEN IT CAME TO DANIELS.
HE'S DEAD, SIR.
HAVE OUR GUESTS LEFT YET?
NO. THE PLUME IS JUST BEGINNING.
ENTERPRISE TO CAPTAIN FRADDOCK.
Fraddock.
I'M LOOKING FOR ONE
OF YOUR PASSENGERS.
HAVE ANY OF THE ONES
WHO WERE HERE RETURNED
IN THE LAST HOUR OR SO?
-None.
-YOU'RE SURE?
The hatch has been sealed
the entire time.
THANKS.
ARCHER OUT.
MR. REED.
YES, SIR.
We've got a Suliban
loose on the ship.
I WANT YOU TO LOCK DOWN
EVERY OUTER DOOR AND EXIT HATCH.
POST SECURITY TEAMS
ON ALL DECKS.
Understood.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN FIND HIM
USING DANIELS' SENSORS?
TUCKER: I CAN SURE AS HELL TRY.
GET TO ENGINEERING.
YES, SIR.
T'POL.
THANKS, DOC.
CAPTAIN?
IT'S GONE. HE TOOK IT.
TOOK WHAT?
THE DEVICE I TOLD YOU ABOUT.
THE ONE DANIELS USED TO SHOW ME
ALL THOSE THINGS.
THAT KIND OF INFORMATION
COULD GIVE AN ADVANTAGE
TO WHOMEVER SILIK'S WORKING FOR.
Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
SOMEONE JUST USED OUR COM SYSTEM
TO TRANSMIT A MESSAGE.
WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE?
It's encrypted, sir.
[ RUMBLING ]
ARCHER: ANYTHING?
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T MAKE HEADS OR TAILS
OF MOST OF THIS.
THESE MIGHT REPRESENT
SULIBAN BIO-SIGNS,
BUT I WOULDN'T BET ON IT.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
B-DECK. SERVICE JUNCTION 59.
SOMEBODY'S TRYING TO BYPASS THE
LOCK-OUT CODES FOR LAUNCH BAY 2.
ARCHER: TELL MALCOLM TO MEET ME
WITH A SECURITY TEAM.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN,
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
THAT MIGHT GIVE YOU A LEG UP.
IT LOOKS LIKE HE
SLIPPED THROUGH HERE.
WE COULD REMOVE THESE CONDUITS,
BUT IT WOULD TAKE SOME TIME.
SIR?
STAY HERE.
[ THUMP ]
SILIK: VERY CLEVER.
CAREFUL, JON.
IT'D BE A SHAME TO TRIGGER
ANOTHER ANTIMATTER CASCADE.
THERE'D BE NOBODY
HERE TO STOP IT.
PUT THAT DEVICE
ON THE FLOOR.
IT WOULD BE IN YOUR BEST
INTEREST TO LET ME TAKE IT.
YOU KEEP SAYING
YOU'RE HERE TO HELP US,
BUT I CAN'T STOP WONDERING
WHAT KIND OF GENETIC
ENHANCEMENTS YOU'LL GET FOR
BRINGING BACK THAT LITTLE PRIZE.
EYES IN THE BACK OF YOUR HEAD?
A PAIR OF WINGS?
THAT'S A CYNICAL ATTITUDE, JON.
I THOUGHT YOUR SPECIES
WAS MORE TRUSTING.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ METALLIC CLANK ]
THERE'S A VESSEL APPROACHING.
NO BIGGER THAN A SHUTTLEPOD.
IT'S SULIBAN.
I'M NOT GOING TO ASK YOU AGAIN.
PUT IT DOWN.
YOU'RE GOING TO KILL ME
AFTER I SAVED YOUR LIFE?
YOU MAY HAVE ENDANGERED
YOUR FUTURE, JON.
[ KLAXON BLARES ]
[ WHOOSHING ]
[ WHOOSHING CONTINUES ]
[ GASPING ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
YEAH.
A SULIBAN VESSEL
JUST TOOK SOMETHING IN
AND WENT TO WARP.
SHOULD WE GO AFTER THEM?
NO.
[ GASPING ]
LET THEM GO.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
ARCHER: COME IN.
THE TRANSPORT SHIP HAS LEFT.
WE'RE READY TO RESUME COURSE.
T'POL: HAVE YOU LEARNED
HOW IT WORKS?
NOT A CLUE.
[ SIGHS ]
STARFLEET'S IN STORE
FOR ONE HELL OF A REPORT.
I'M NOT QUITE SURE
WHERE TO BEGIN.
I'D BE GLAD TO HELP.
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU, BUT, UH...
I COULD USE
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
AGREED.
MR. REED, ASSIGN NEW QUARTERS
TO DANIELS' ROOMMATE
AND SEAL OFF CABIN E-14.
IT'S OFF-LIMITS
TILL FURTHER NOTICE.
AYE, SIR.
GOD KNOWS WHAT ELSE IS IN THERE.
LET'S GET BACK ON THE ROAD,
TRAVIS.