REED: ECHO II IS AWAY, SIR.
A CLEAN LAUNCH.
T'POL: IT'S MADE CONTACT
WITH ECHO I.
HOW LONG BEFORE WE GET
SUBSPACE ONLINE?
HOSHI: I'D LIKE TO SEND
A FEW TEST TRANSMISSIONS
TO CALIBRATE AMPLIFIERS.
AN HOUR.
ARCHER: MY GUESS IS WE HAVE
A LOT OF PEOPLE ON BOARD
WAITING TO CALL HOME.
[ BEEPING ]
REED: A VESSEL IS DROPPING
OUT OF WARP, CAPTAIN.
12 KILOMETERS DEAD AHEAD.
ARCHER: PUT IT UP.
LOOK FAMILIAR?
T'POL: I DON'T RECOGNIZE
THE CONFIGURATION.
GOOD. HAIL THEM.
[ BEEPING ]
THIS IS THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU?
MY NAME IS JONATHAN ARCHER.
WE'RE ON A MISSION
OF EXPLORATION
FROM THE PLANET EARTH.
HOSHI?
HOSHI: THE CHANNEL'S OPEN, SIR.
DO YOU NEED ASSISTANCE?
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO TALK,
THAT'S FINE,
BUT...YOU DROPPED IN ON US.
WAS IT SOMETHING I SAID?
DID YOU GET ANYTHING
ON SENSORS?
REED: NO.
ARCHER: "NO" WHAT?
NO BIO-SIGNS.
NO PROPULSION,
NO WEAPON SIGNATURES.
NO READINGS AT ALL.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARE THERE ANY INHABITED
SYSTEMS NEARBY?
T'POL: NONE.
ARCHER: WHY FLY RIGHT UP TO US
JUST TO GIVE US
THE SILENT TREATMENT?
HOSHI: MAYBE THEY GOT
OUR SIGNAL,
BUT IT DIDN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE TO THEM.
OUR TRANSLATOR
IS FAR FROM PERFECT.
T'POL: I WOULDN'T TAKE OFFENSE.
NOT EVERY SPECIES HAS MOTIVES
THAT CAN BE UNDERSTOOD
IN HUMAN TERMS.
MAYWEATHER: MAYBE THEY
CHECKED US OUT
AND DECIDED WE WEREN'T
VERY INTERESTING.
REED: US, NOT INTERESTING?
LET'S CALIBRATE
THE SUBSPACE AMPLIFIER.
AT LEAST THE PEOPLE BACK HOME
WANT TO TALK TO US.
HOSHI: [ CLEARS THROAT ]
SIR?
[ WHISPERING ]
I tracked them down.
It took me all week.
Archer: Where are they?
Hoshi: Kota Baharu--
it's in Malaysia.
Archer: What time is it there?
Hoshi: A little after
9:00 at night.
Archer: That shouldn't be
too late.
Let's break in
that new amplifier.
I'll be in my ready room.
WOMAN: IS HE ALL RIGHT?
ARCHER: HE'S FINE.
MAN: IS HE IN SOME KIND
OF TROUBLE?
[ CHUCKLING ] NO, SIR.
MALCOLM'S DOING A GREAT JOB.
I'M SURE YOU KNOW IT'S HIS
BIRTHDAY IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
WOMAN: YES. YES, IT IS.
SEPTEMBER 2nd.
MAN: WE HAVEN'T SEEN OUR SON
ON HIS BIRTHDAY
FOR QUITE A FEW YEARS.
WOMAN: HE CALLED FROM
SAN FRANCISCO TO LET US KNOW
HE'D BEEN ASSIGNED TO
ENTERPRISE,
BUT WE HAVEN'T HEARD
FROM HIM SINCE.
MAN: WHAT ARE MALCOLM'S DUTIES
ON YOUR SHIP, CAPTAIN?
HE'S MY ARMORY OFFICER.
MAN: WELL. HIS GRANDFATHER
WOULD BE PLEASED.
HE WAS AN ORDNANCE OFFICER
HIMSELF IN THE ROYAL NAVY.
ARCHER: IT MUST BE
IN MALCOLM'S BLOOD.
WOMAN: THE REEDS HAVE BEEN
NAVY MEN FOR GENERATIONS.
MAN: UNTIL MALCOLM DECIDED
TO JOIN THE STARFLEET.
I SUPPOSE THE OCEAN
WASN'T BIG ENOUGH FOR HIM.
HE'S A LONG WAY FROM HOME,
IN ANY CASE, MR. REED.
I'D LIKE TO DO SOMETHING
FOR HIS BIRTHDAY,
MAKE HIM A SPECIAL DINNER.
I WAS HOPING YOU COULD TELL ME
WHAT HE LIKES TO EAT.
WOMAN: CAPTAIN, MALCOLM'S
NEVER BEEN COMFORTABLE
MAKING REQUESTS.
I'M NOT SURE I UNDERSTAND.
MAN: HE ALWAYS ATE WHATEVER
WAS PUT IN FRONT OF HIM.
ARE YOU SAYING HE DOESN'T HAVE
A FAVORITE FOOD?
WOMAN: NOT THAT HE'S EVER
TOLD ME.
WELL...
IF YOU HAPPEN TO THINK
OF ANYTHING,
YOU CAN ALWAYS CONTACT ME
THROUGH STARFLEET.
WOMAN: GIVE MALCOLM OUR BEST.
I WILL.
MAN: SAFE JOURNEY, CAPTAIN.
[ BEEPING ]
HOSHI: HOW'D IT GO?
ARCHER: COULD'VE GONE BETTER.
APPARENTLY, HE HASN'T CALLED
HOME SINCE WE LEFT EARTH.
I WANT YOU TO FIND OUT
WHAT HE LIKES TO EAT.
ME, SIR?
ARCHER: BUT DON'T LET
MALCOLM KNOW.
HOSHI: MAYBE THIS IS MORE
IN CHEF'S AREA.
NO, WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
A DELICATE ASSIGNMENT, HOSHI.
IT NEEDS YOUR FINESSE.
SIR, I'M RUNNING
A DIAGNOSTIC ON
OUR SUBSPACE
TRANSCEIVER ARRAY.
GET SOME HELP IF YOU NEED IT,
BUT MAKE THIS A TOP PRIORITY.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
HOSHI: YES, SIR.
ARCHER: WHERE WERE YOU
AT DINNER?
TUCKER: I ATE IN MY QUARTERS.
NOW THAT WE'VE GOT
THE AMPLIFIER WORKING,
I WANTED TO ANSWER
A FEW LETTERS.
ARCHER: YOU MISSED T'POL'S
LATEST BOUT WITH CHOPSTICKS.
TUCKER: DAMN, DINNER AND A SHOW.
[ ARCHER CHUCKLES ]
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GONNA UPGRADE THIS.
THAT IS THE UPGRADE.
WELL, IF YOU WANT,
I CAN CHANGE THE COLOR.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE WORD
FROM HOME?
TUCKER: OH, THE USUAL--
ENGINEERING UPDATES.
OH, AND DUVALL GOT PROMOTED.
THEY'RE GIVING HIM
THE SHENANDOAH.
ARCHER: DUVALL GOT
HIS OWN COMMAND?
THANK GOD WE'RE
100 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
[ CHUCKLING ]
AND I GOT A LETTER
FROM NATALIE.
ARCHER:  THE NATALIE,
FROM PENSACOLA?
YEP.
NATALIE FROM PENSACOLA.
LOOKS LIKE WE'VE GOT A CHARGE
IMBALANCE IN THIS MANIFOLD.
I'LL GET RIGHT ON IT.
TRIP?
YOU KNOW, THEY SAY LONG-DISTANCE
RELATIONSHIPS NEVER WORK.
WELL...THIS IS ABOUT
AS LONG DISTANCE AS YOU CAN GET.
ARE YOU OK?
OH, YEAH. I JUST--
I JUST WISH I'D HAVE
HAD THE CHANCE
TO SAY GOODBYE FACE-TO-FACE.
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
DO YOU SPEND MUCH TIME
WITH MALCOLM?
TUCKER: I WAS IN THE ARMORY
YESTERDAY FOR A FEW HOURS,
SWAPPING OUT SOME POWER RELAYS.
ARCHER: YOU TALK ABOUT
ANYTHING INTERESTING?
TUCKER: POWER RELAYS.
ARCHER: I TALKED TO HIS PARENTS
THIS MORNING.
TUCKER: REALLY?
ARCHER: YEAH.
STAY HERE.
IF I ASKED YOUR PARENTS
WHAT YOU LIKE TO EAT,
WOULD THEY BE ABLE
TO TELL ME?
TUCKER: ARE YOU KIDDING?
MY MOM WOULD GIVE YOU HER RECIPE
FOR PAN-FRIED CATFISH
AND WOULDN'T LET YOU GO
TILL YOU PROMISED
NOT TO SCREW IT UP.
[ ARCHER CHUCKLES ]
ARCHER: MALCOLM'S PARENTS DIDN'T
KNOW WHAT HIS FAVORITE FOOD WAS.
THEY DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
HE WAS AN ARMORY OFFICER.
TUCKER: THAT'S STRANGE.
ARCHER: IT MADE ME THINK.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT MUCH
ABOUT MALCOLM, DO WE?
[ RUMBLING ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
T'Pol: Bridge to the Captain.
GO AHEAD.
T'Pol: The alien vessel
has returned.
ARCHER: GUESS WE WEREN'T
SO UNINTERESTING AFTER ALL.
T'POL: THEY DROPPED OUT OF WARP
500 KILOMETERS, DEAD AHEAD.
MAYWEATHER: I HAD TO
REVERSE ENGINES
TO KEEP FROM
BANGING INTO THEM.
ARCHER: LET'S TRY THIS AGAIN.
[ BEEPING ]
WELCOME BACK.
I WAS HOPING WE'D HAVE
AN OPPORTUNITY TO MEET AGAIN.
THE PRIMARY MISSION OF MY SHIP
IS TO MAKE PEACEFUL CONTACT
WITH OTHER SPECIES.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING WE CAN DO TO
ASSURE YOU OF OUR INTENTIONS...
WELL...
IT'S BEEN NICE TALKING TO YOU.
LET'S DO THIS AGAIN SOMETIME.
HOSHI: I'M PICKING UP SOMETHING.
CAN YOU TRANSLATE IT?
HOSHI: I--I DON'T THINK
IT'S A LANGUAGE.
[ SHRILL NOISE ]
[ ALL GROANING ]
WE'RE BEING SCANNED.
[ GRUNTS ]
HULL PLATING?
IT'S OFF-LINE!
HARD ABOUT!
MAYWEATHER: THEY'VE GONE
TO WARP, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
EVERYBODY OK?
REED: DAMAGE REPORTS
ARE COMING IN, SIR.
NO ONE'S BEEN HURT.
ARCHER: WHAT THE HELL
WAS THAT ABOUT?
REED: CAPTAIN?
WHEN THEY FIRED THEIR WEAPON,
THEY DROPPED THEIR SHIELDING
FOR ABOUT TWO SECONDS.
I WAS ABLE TO TAKE SOME SCANS.
WHAT DID YOU GET?
BIO-SIGNS--
AT LEAST 15, MAYBE MORE.
THEIR DNA DOESN'T MATCH ANYTHING
IN OUR DATABASE.
REED: IT'S A GOOD THING
THEY'RE GONE.
I DOUBT VERY MUCH
OUR TORPEDOES
COULD'VE PENETRATED
THEIR SHIELDING.
STAY ON LONG-RANGE SCANNERS.
IF THEY COME ANYWHERE NEAR US,
I WANT TO KNOW.
T'POL.
TUCKER: THAT SUPPORT FRAME'S
BENT.
WE'LL NEED TO REINFORCE IT.
ARCHER: HOW BAD IS IT?
TUCKER: IF THAT LAST SHOT HAD
BEEN ABOUT A HALF-METER HIGHER,
WE'D BE LOOKING AT STARS.
ARCHER: HOLD IT A MINUTE.
THERE WERE 13 PEOPLE WORKING
IN THIS SECTION, CAPTAIN,
INCLUDING YOURS TRULY.
IF THAT BULKHEAD HAD BLOWN...
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
ARCHER: DID YOUR PEOPLE RUN INTO
AS MANY HOSTILE ALIENS
WHEN THEY FIRST WENT
INTO DEEP SPACE?
T'POL: IT WAS A DIFFERENT TIME.
ARCHER: HOW SO?
T'POL: THERE WERE FEWER
WARP-CAPABLE SPECIES.
ARCHER: THIS SHIP
JUST ISN'T EQUIPPED TO HANDLE
SOME OF THE THREATS
WE'RE COMING UP AGAINST.
IT'S TIME WE DO
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT.
T'POL: WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING?
ARCHER: ENTERPRISE WAS FITTED
WITH PHASE CANNON PORTS.
BUT SINCE WE LEFT SPACEDOCK
A FEW WEEKS AHEAD OF SCHEDULE,
THE CANNONS
WERE NEVER INSTALLED.
I THINK IT'S TIME THEY WERE.
WE SHOULD HEAD BACK TO EARTH.
JUST GIVE US TWO WEEKS, CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: I KNOW WE CAN DO IT.
MOST OF THE STUFF WE NEED
IS ALREADY ON THE SHIP.
ARCHER: THE ARMORY TEAM
AT JUPITER STATION
IS TRAINED FOR
THIS KIND OF WORK.
IF WE'RE GONNA DO THIS,
LET'S DO IT RIGHT.
TUCKER: MY ENGINEERS ARE
JUST AS GOOD AS THEY ARE.
ARCHER: I KNOW THAT, TRIP.
BUT WE HAVE OTHER SYSTEMS
THAT COULD USE OVERHAULS.
LOOK AT THE BRIGHT SIDE.
YOU'VE GOT A CHANCE
TO SAY GOODBYE TO NATALIE.
REED: SIR?
WITH YOUR PERMISSION, WE COULD
AT LEAST BEGIN THE WORK,
GET A FEW THINGS STARTED
FOR JUPITER STATION.
TUCKER: IT'LL CUT DOWN THE TIME
WE'LL HAVE TO SPEND
IN SPACEDOCK.
DO WHAT YOU CAN.
[ BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO MAYWEATHER.
Mayweather: Go ahead, Captain.
WE'RE HEADING HOME.
REED: THIS, LADIES
AND GENTLEMEN,
IS A PHASE-MODULATED
ENERGY WEAPON.
IT'S RATED FOR A MAXIMUM
POWER OUTPUT
OF 500 GIGAJOULES.
ENTERPRISE WAS DESIGNED
TO CARRY THREE OF THEM.
WE HAVE ONE, AND IT'S
ONLY A PROTOTYPE.
TUCKER: OUR JOB IS TO GET IT
UP AND RUNNING
AND BUILD TWO MORE
FROM SCRATCH.
THE CAPTAIN IS TAKING US BACK
BECAUSE HE THINKS
THIS WORK OUGHT TO BE DONE
BY THE BOYS IN SPACEDOCK.
REED: FAR BE IT FROM ME TO
QUESTION THE CAPTAIN'S JUDGMENT,
BUT COMMANDER TUCKER
AND I BELIEVE
WE CAN DO THIS OURSELVES.
TUCKER: THAT MEANS
DOUBLE SHIFTS.
BY THE TIME WE REACH
JUPITER STATION,
I DON'T WANT THEIR ENGINEERS
TO HAVE A THING TO DO
BUT GIVE US A WASH AND A WAX.
[ ENGINEERS CHUCKLE ]
ANY QUESTIONS?
ARE WE EXPECTING
ANOTHER ATTACK, SIR?
TUCKER: WE ALL SIGNED UP
FOR THIS TRIP BECAUSE WE WANTED
TO DO SOMETHING NO ONE
HAD EVER DONE BEFORE,
NOT BECAUSE WE THOUGHT
IT'D BE EASY
OR SAFE.
BUT WE'RE NOT HERE
TO TAKE FOOLISH RISKS.
THE CAPTAIN
AND THE REST OF THE CREW
ARE DEPENDING ON US
TO KEEP ENTERPRISE
READY FOR ANYTHING.
REED: AND ONCE WE GET
THESE PHASE CANNONS ONLINE,
WE'LL HAVE A LOT MORE FIREPOWER
TO DO JUST THAT.
TUCKER: SO WHAT ARE YOU
STANDING AROUND FOR?
HE ONCE TOLD ME
THAT HE LOVED TO EAT OCTOPUS,
ESPECIALLY
THE LITTLE SUCTION CUPS,
BUT I THINK
HE WAS PULLING MY LEG.
YOU CAN NEVER TELL WHETHER
MY BROTHER'S JOKING OR NOT.
CAN I TALK TO HIM?
WE REALLY WOULD LIKE
TO KEEP THIS A SURPRISE.
OH, RIGHT. THE DINNER.
I REMEMBER ONE TIME--THIS
WAS AT LEAST 10 YEARS AGO--
HE WENT FOR A WHOLE WEEK
WITHOUT EATING.
HOSHI: REALLY?
GOT BY ON NOTHING BUT WATER
AND A LITTLE APPLE JUICE.
WHY?
SOME SORT OF SURVIVAL TRAINING,
OR WAS IT A CONTEST?
WHEN HE STARTED EATING AGAIN,
DO YOU REMEMBER
THE FIRST THING HE WANTED?
HE WAS SO WEAK,
HE COULD BARELY GET OUT OF BED.
FOR TWO DAYS, ALL HE HAD
WAS PROTEIN CONCENTRATE.
HOSHI: WHEN YOU TWO
WERE GROWING UP,
HE NEVER SAID,
"HEY, LET'S GO OUT FOR PIZZA,"
OR, "BOY, I'D LOVE
SOME INDIAN FOOD"?
NOT THAT I REMEMBER.
MALCOLM ISN'T THE EASIEST
PERSON TO GET TO KNOW.
I'M FIGURING THAT OUT.
WHEN WE WERE TRAINING
IN SAN FRANCISCO,
THERE WAS A LITTLE RESTAURANT
ON THE EMBARCADERO
HE LIKED TO GO TO.
THEY HAD A SPECIALTY--
SOME KIND OF...FISH, I THINK.
WHAT KIND?
HALIBUT?
UH, SWORDFISH?
NO.
MAHIMAHI? SCALLOPS?
I HAD SEA BASS.
GREAT! AND MALCOLM?
I DON'T REMEMBER.
TRY, PLEASE.
MAUREEN.
IS THAT A FISH?
NO, SHE WAS THE WAITRESS.
[ CHUCKLING ]
THAT'S WHY MALCOLM WANTED
TO GO THERE!
HE HAD A THING FOR HER!
I THINK HE HATES FISH.
HOSHI: THANKS.
[ BEEPS ]
SO HOW'S YOUR
SECRET MISSION COMING?
HOSHI: I'VE TALKED TO HIS
SISTER, HIS BEST FRIEND,
HIS UNCLE ARCHIE,
HIS TWO SPINSTER AUNTS.
THE MOST ANYONE SEEMS
TO KNOW ABOUT HIS
EATING HABITS IS THAT
HE...OCCASIONALLY EATS.
[ MAYWEATHER CHUCKLES ]
T'POL: ENSIGN?
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT MR. REED,
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD ASK HIM.
HOSHI: ANYONE SITTING HERE?
REED: UH, NO.
PLEASE.
HOSHI: OOH.
THIS IS THE FIRST CHANCE
I'VE HAD TO EAT ALL DAY.
REED: OHH.
TELL ME ABOUT IT.
I HAVEN'T SET FOOT OUTSIDE
THE ARMORY SINCE 0700.
HOSHI: HOW'S YOUR RAVIOLI?
REED: YEAH, IT'S FINE.
HOSHI: NOTHING LIKE
A NICE PLATE OF PASTA.
REED: MM-HMM.
YOU KNOW,
I USED TO LOVE TO COOK,
BUT I NEVER GET
A CHANCE TO ANYMORE--
THE WAY THAT CHEF
PROTECTS THE GALLEY.
ONE OF THESE NIGHTS,
I SHOULD FIX SOMETHING MYSELF.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
REED: I'M SORRY.
HOSHI: YOU'D LOVE MY ENCHILADAS.
REED: ENCHILADAS?
HOSHI: WELL, IF YOU DON'T LIKE
THEM, I CAN FIX SOMETHING ELSE.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE FOOD?
[ SCOFFS ]
UH, I APPRECIATE THE OFFER,
BUT IT--
IT REALLY ISN'T NECESSARY.
HOSHI: AREN'T YOU GETTING
A LITTLE TIRED
OF HAVING TO EAT WHATEVER
CHEF HAPPENS TO SERVE?
REED: NO, HE'S A--
HE'S A FINE COOK.
HOSHI: DON'T GET ME WRONG.
HE'S TERRIFIC.
IT'S JUST THAT DINNER
IN THE MESS HALL CAN...
LACK A CERTAIN
PERSONAL TOUCH.
I'VE GOT A HOT PLATE
IN MY QUARTERS.
THAT'S...VERY FLATTERING AND...
I'M JUST NOT SURE IT
WOULD BE APPROPRIATE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, UM...WE WORK
TOGETHER AND, UH,
IT JUST MIGHT BE
A LITTLE...AWKWARD--
SERVING ON THE SAME SHIP.
HOSHI: WHAT DOES THAT
HAVE TO DO WITH...
OH.
[ LAUGHING ]
NO, I DIDN'T--
I DIDN'T MEAN TO, UM...
IMPLY ANYTHING OTHER THAN
JUST MAKING DINNER, LIEUTENANT.
REED: THEN, UH,
IT'S MY MISTAKE, ENSIGN.
HOSHI: NO, UH, IT'S MY FAULT.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE...
YEAH, I'LL--I'LL JUST--
REED: NO, NO.
PLEASE, FINISH YOUR DINNER.
HOSHI: NO, NO. YOU'VE GOT
A LOT OF WORK TO DO, SO...
[ DOOR OPENS ]
CAPTAIN, I'M DETECTING
A SHIP, DEAD ASTERN--
8,000 METERS.
ARCHER: LET ME GUESS--
OUR SHADOW?
[ BEEPING ]
CLOSING TO 7,000.
T'POL: 6,000.
POLARIZE THE HULL PLATING.
[ RUMBLING ]
REED TO BRIDGE.
ARMORY, REPORT.
GET TO YOUR STATIONS. MOVE.
WARP DRIVE IS OFFLINE.
T'POL: MAIN POWER IS DOWN.
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER: TORPEDOES.
TACTICAL SYSTEMS ARE DOWN.
ARCHER: WHY DON'T YOU SAVE TIME
AND TELL ME WHAT ISN'T DOWN?
THE OUTER DOORS
IN LAUNCH BAY 2 ARE OPENING.
ARCHER: SEAL THEM.
T'POL: I CAN'T.
[ CLATTERING ]
GET AWAY FROM THOSE MEN!
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER: GO.
ARCHER TO SICK BAY.
Phlox: Phlox here, Captain.
REPORT TO E-DECK, SECTION 7!
THIS IS AN EMERGENCY!
Phlox: On my way.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Crewman: Security
to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
Crewman: The aliens
are gone, sir.
They've launched their shuttle.
[ RUMBLING ]
BRIDGE, REPORT!
T'Pol: The alien vessel
has gone to warp,
but that last shot damaged
our port nacelle.
We're venting drive plasma.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ BEEPS ]
ARCHER: DOCTOR?
PHLOX: [SIGHS]
I'VE STABILIZED THEM,
BUT THEY WERE SUBJECTED
TO SOME RATHER INVASIVE SCANS.
ARCHER: WILL THEY BE ALL RIGHT?
PHLOX: THERE COULD BE SOME
RESIDUAL NEUROLOGICAL DAMAGE.
I'M DOING EVERYTHING I CAN.
ARCHER: HAVE YOU EVER HEARD
OF ANYTHING LIKE THIS?
T'POL: NO.
ARCHER: ARE THERE
ANY VULCAN RECORDS
OF A SPECIES THAT USES
SIMILAR TACTICS?
AND I DON'T CARE HOW CLASSIFIED
THEY MIGHT BE.
T'POL: NONE THAT I KNOW OF,
CAPTAIN.
FIND OUT WHAT YOU CAN.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Tucker: Tucker to Archer.
GO AHEAD.
TUCKER: WE'VE GOT
THE PLASMA LEAK UNDER CONTROL,
BUT OUR PORT NACELLE
TOOK A LOT OF DAMAGE.
Archer: How long before
we can go to warp?
TUCKER: A COUPLE OF DAYS.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT
IMPULSE POWER?
Tucker: Well, that's
the good news.
IT SHOULD BE BACK ONLINE
IN A FEW MINUTES.
ARCHER: I'LL TAKE
ALL THE GOOD NEWS I CAN GET.
KEEP ME POSTED, DOCTOR.
THERE ARE NO VULCAN SHIPS
WITHIN SCANNING RANGE.
MAYWEATHER: SIR, WE COULD TRY TO
CONTACT THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND.
THEY'RE ONLY TWO DAYS AWAY
AT WARP 6.
I'M SURE THEY'D GIVE US A HAND.
ARCHER: I'M SURE THEY WOULD.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
I CAN'T RAISE VULCAN.
IT'S FUNNY--I RAN A DIAGNOSTIC
AFTER THE ATTACK,
BUT NOW ECHO II WON'T RESPOND.
THAT'S BECAUSE IT ISN'T THERE.
WHAT?
THERE'S NOTHING BUT DEBRIS
AT THE COORDINATES
WHERE WE DEPLOYED THE AMPLIFIER.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT ECHO I?
DESTROYED, AS WELL.
THE STABILIZER ON CANNON PORT 2
CHECKS OUT OK, SIR.
REED: PORT 2 OR PORT 1?
CREWMAN: PORT 1, SIR. SORRY.
REED: GET IT RIGHT!
START ON THOSE BEAM EMITTERS.
CREWMAN: YES, SIR.
TUCKER: TARGETING SCANNERS
WILL BE ONLINE IN AN HOUR.
REED: WE SHOULD BE ALIGNING THEM
BY NOW, NOT INSTALLING THEM.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
TUCKER: YOU WERE A LITTLE HARD
ON EDDIE.
EVERYONE IS BUSTING THEIR TAILS
TO GET THIS JOB DONE.
REED: AAH!
TUCKER: YOU OK?
REED: YEAH!
[ GROANING ]
FINE.
I TOLD THEM TO DEPOLARIZE
THESE RELAYS!
TUCKER: WHAT WERE YOU
TRYING TO DO?
REED: BYPASS THE E.P.S. GRID.
TUCKER: WHY?
REED: WELL, WE COULD DRAW POWER
FOR THE CANNONS
DIRECTLY
FROM THE IMPULSE ENGINES.
ARE YOU TRYING TO MAKE THIS
BLOW UP IN YOUR FACE?
THE RELAYS WERE RATED
TO HANDLE THAT MUCH POWER.
TUCKER: WHAT IF THERE'S A SURGE?
REED: OH, I'VE THOUGHT OF THAT.
THESE INVERTERS WERE DESIGNED
TO CUT IN AT THE FIRST SIGN
OF AN OVERLOAD.
WE GOT TO DO THIS BY THE BOOK,
OR WE'LL END UP
BLOWING A BIGGER HOLE
IN OURSELVES THAN THE BAD GUYS.
I'VE RUN A DOZEN SIMULATIONS.
IT'S AN ACCEPTABLE RISK.
WHEN IT COMES
TO MODIFYING SHIP SYSTEMS,
WHY DON'T YOU LET
THE CHIEF ENGINEER DECIDE
WHAT'S AN ACCEPTABLE RISK?
SIR...
IF WE DO THIS BY THE BOOK,
THOSE ALIENS ARE LIKELY
TO BE BACK BEFORE WE'RE DONE.
TUCKER: I WANT TO GET THIS JOB
DONE AS QUICKLY AS YOU DO,
LIEUTENANT, BUT NOT IF IT MEANS
TAKING SHORTCUTS
THAT COULD GET
OUR PEOPLE KILLED.
REED: YES, SIR.
[ FOOTSTEPS RETREAT ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ARCHER: DON'T YOU EVER REST?
TUCKER: YOU KNOW, I CAN'T SLEEP
WITHOUT THE WARP ENGINES ONLINE.
IF I DON'T FEEL
THOSE VIBRATIONS,
SOMETHING JUST
DOESN'T SEEM RIGHT.
WELL, I HOPE YOU GET THEM FIXED
SOON BECAUSE YOU LOOK LIKE HELL.
WELL, WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
CAPTAIN,
YOU SHOULDN'T BE TALKING.
ARCHER: HOW'S IT COMING?
TUCKER: THEY'LL BE ONLINE
BY THE END OF THE DAY TOMORROW,
GUARANTEED.
COULD YOU CHECK
THE DILITHIUM ALIGNMENT FOR ME?
ARCHER: SURE.
ARCHER: .06 MICRONS.
AT LEAST WE'LL BE FLYING HOME
UNDER OUR OWN POWER.
LET ME KNOW
IF IT DROPS BELOW .03.
I TRIED TO GET A MESSAGE
TO THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND,
BUT IT DIDN'T GO THROUGH.
IF IT HAD, WE'D BE EXPECTING
A SURAK-CLASS SHIP TOMORROW,
OH SO POLITELY
OFFERING TO HELP US.
WELL, THE VULCANS
WOULD'VE LOVED THAT--
TOWING THE PRIDE OF STARFLEET
BACK TO BASE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD THANK
OUR VISITORS
FOR BLOWING UP
THE SUBSPACE AMPLIFIERS.
[ BEEPING ]
HOLDING AT .05.
KEEP AN EYE ON IT.
YOU LOOKING FORWARD
TO SEEING EARTH?
SURE.
I JUST...DIDN'T THINK
I'D BE SEEING IT SO SOON.
THIS TIME...
WE WON'T BE LEAVING
BEFORE WE'RE READY.
ARE YOUR EARS
A LITTLE POINTIER THAN USUAL?
ARCHER: I NEV--
I NEVER SAID
WE DIDN'T BELONG OUT HERE.
I JUST WISH WE'D HAVE...
LAUNCHED WITH ALL
OUR SYSTEMS ONLINE,
ESPECIALLY WEAPONS.
IF WE HADN'T LAUNCHED
WHEN WE DID,
THEY'D HAVE SENT KLAANG
BACK TO KRONOS IN A BOX.
I KEEP REMINDING MYSELF OF THAT.
BUT I RUSHED US OUT OF SPACEDOCK
BECAUSE I HAD
SOMETHING TO PROVE.
AND I RISKED THE LIVES OF...
81 HUMANS, A VULCAN,
AND A DENOBULAN TO DO IT.
DON'T FORGET PORTHOS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THANKS.
IN THE OLD DAYS,
ASTRONAUTS RODE ROCKETS
WITH MILLIONS OF LITERS
OF HYDROGEN
BURNING UNDER THEIR SEATS.
YOU THINK THEY SAID,
"GEE, I'D LOVE TO GO
TO THE MOON TODAY,
BUT IT SEEMS A LITTLE RISKY"?
I THINK IF YOU ASKED
ANYONE ON BOARD
WHETHER THEY THOUGHT
THIS MISSION WAS WORTH THE RISK,
YOU'D GET THE SAME ANSWER
FROM EVERY ONE OF THEM.
LET ME KNOW
WHEN WE'RE READY TO GO TO WARP.
AYE, SIR.
TUCKER: HAVE YOU STILL GOT
THOSE GUNS OF YOURS
HOOKED UP
TO THE IMPULSE ENGINES?
REED: I'M JUST
DISCONNECTING THEM NOW.
TUCKER: HANG ON A MINUTE.
YOU'RE SURE THIS WILL WORK?
REED: YES, COMMANDER, I AM.
TUCKER: THEN, BASED ON
THE RECOMMENDATION
OF THE ARMORY OFFICER,
THE CHIEF ENGINEER FINDS
THE LEVEL OF RISK ACCEPTABLE.
IN THAT CASE,
IF THE CHIEF ENGINEER WOULDN'T
MIND GETTING HIS HANDS DIRTY,
I COULD USE SOME HELP.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SEPTEMBER 1, 2151.
IT'S BEEN TWO DAYS NOW WITH
NO SIGN OF THE ALIEN VESSEL.
MY CREW HAS MANAGED TO DO
IN 48 HOURS
WHAT WOULD HAVE TAKEN THE
ARMORY TEAM AT JUPITER STATION
AT LEAST A WEEK.
TO SAY THAT I'M PROUD OF THEM
WOULD BE AN UNDERSTATEMENT.
WE'RE PREPARING OUR FIRST TEST.
EVERYBODY HAS
THEIR FINGERS CROSSED,
INCLUDING ME.
ARCHER: YOU'RE SURE
THERE'S NOTHING DOWN THERE?
T'POL: YES, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: NOT EVEN A MICROBE?
I DON'T WANT TO BLOW UP
SOMETHING THAT COULD EVOLVE
INTO A SENTIENT SPECIES
IN A COUPLE OF BILLION YEARS.
T'POL: THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO LIEUTENANT REED.
HAVE YOU GOT A LOCK?
Reed: Yes, Captain.
LET'S START SMALL.
SHAVE A COUPLE OF METERS
OFF THE TOP OF THAT PEAK.
ACQUIRING THE TARGET.
[ BEEPING ]
FULL POWER TO THE PRIMARY COILS.
PHASE CANNONS ONE AND TWO
STANDING BY.
MR. REED...
THE HONOR IS ALL YOURS.
I JUST ASKED
FOR A LITTLE OFF THE TOP!
-CHECK THE CANNONS!
-YES, SIR.
BE CAREFUL DOWN THERE.
THE BLAST YIELD
WAS 10 TIMES WHAT WE EXPECTED.
Archer: What happened?
SOMETHING OVERLOADED
THE PHASE MODULATORS.
THE PLASMA RECOIL BLEW OUT
RELAYS ACROSS DECKS "C" AND "D."
I'M GETTING AN ANOMALOUS
READING FROM LAUNCH BAY 2.
TRIP, T'POL.
TUCKER: THERE.
WHAT'S THAT?
ARCHER: YOU THINK THAT'S WHAT'S
CAUSING THE POWER SURGE?
T'POL: IT'S VERY LIKELY.
IT'S PUTTING OUT
A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF ENERGY,
OVER 600 MEGAJOULES.
REED: THEY'RE TOYING WITH US.
THEY WANT US TO KNOW THEY CAN
DESTROY US WHENEVER THEY WANT,
EVEN WITH OUR OWN WEAPONS.
T'POL: WHATEVER IT IS,
IT'S TAPPED INTO MOST
OF OUR SYSTEMS,
INCLUDING INTERNAL SENSORS AND
COMMUNICATIONS ON EVERY DECK.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ACTIVATE VISUAL SENSOR J-15.
I ASSUME
YOU PLANTED THAT DEVICE
BECAUSE YOU WANTED
TO LEARN MORE ABOUT US.
I'LL BE HAPPY TO GIVE YOU
A QUICK LESSON.
WE'RE NOT HERE TO MAKE ENEMIES.
BUT JUST BECAUSE
WE'RE NOT LOOKING FOR A FIGHT
DOESN'T MEAN
WE'LL RUN AWAY FROM ONE.
YOU MAY THINK
YOU'VE LEFT US DEFENSELESS,
BUT LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING
ABOUT HUMANS.
WE DON'T GIVE UP EASILY.
WE'LL PROTECT ENTERPRISE...
ANY WAY WE CAN.
DOCTOR?
PHLOX: I'LL BE WITH YOU
IN A MOMENT, ENSIGN.
HOSHI: I SEE YOU RELEASED
YOUR PATIENTS.
PHLOX: HMM.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
I SENT THEM BACK
TO THEIR QUARTERS TO REST.
HOSHI: THAT'S GOOD TO HEAR.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
YOU SPEND A LOT OF TIME
IN THE MESS HALL.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD A MEAL
WITH LIEUTENANT REED?
PHLOX: MANY TIMES.
ANY IDEA WHAT
HIS FAVORITE FOOD MIGHT BE?
AH, THE BIRTHDAY DINNER. HMM.
UH, WELL, THE MAN LOVES
A GOOD BREAKFAST.
-LIKE WHAT?
-EGGS.
I'VE SEEN HIM EAT
A LOT OF EGGS.
HOSHI: HOW DOES HE LIKE THEM?
OH, SCRAMBLED, POACHED,
OVER EASY.
MAYBE CHEF COULD MAKE HIM
A...BIG OMELET.
OH, AND HE ENJOYS PANCAKES,
ON OCCASION. HMM.
HE HAS THE ODD HABIT OF
SPREADING PEANUT BUTTER ON THEM.
UH, SAUSAGE--
THAT'S ANOTHER FAVORITE--
AND BACON, TOO,
COME TO THINK OF IT.
IS THERE ANY ONE FOOD
IN PARTICULAR?
HMM...NOT THAT I RECALL.
BREAKING A VULCAN
ENCRYPTION CODE
WOULD BE EASIER THAN THIS.
PHLOX: IF ANYTHING COMES
TO MIND, I'LL, UH, LET YOU KNOW.
HOSHI: I DON'T SUPPOSE SCANNING
HIS TASTE BUDS WOULD HELP?
MEDICALLY SPEAKING, THERE'S
NO ACCOUNTING FOR TASTE.
HOSHI: THANKS, ANYWAY.
PHLOX: MM-HMM.
BROMELIN!
SORRY?
I THINK I CAN HELP YOU, ENSIGN.
[ PHLOX CHUCKLES ]
BUT IT, UH, WOULD MEAN GOING
INTO MR. REED'S MEDICAL RECORDS.
THAT INFORMATION
IS CONFIDENTIAL.
HOSHI: I'M UNDER DIRECT ORDERS
FROM THE CAPTAIN.
COULDN'T YOU MAKE AN EXCEPTION?
PHLOX: UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I SUPPOSE IT WOULDN'T HURT.
HMM.
AH.
I'VE MADE IT A POINT TO STUDY
EACH CREWMAN'S MEDICAL HISTORY,
AND I REMEMBER NOTICING
THAT LIEUTENANT REED
SUFFERS FROM A NUMBER
OF ALLERGIES.
LET'S SEE--DUST MITES, OAK,
POLLEN, TROPICAL GRASSES.
AH! HA HA HA!
HERE IT IS.
HE'S AVERSE TO VARIOUS PLANT
ENZYMES, INCLUDING BROMELIN.
HOSHI: WHAT DOES ALL
OF THIS HAVE TO DO WITH
WHAT HE LIKES TO EAT?
PHLOX: OVER THE LAST
SEVERAL YEARS, HE'S BEEN TAKING
REGULAR INJECTIONS SO THAT HIS
BODY CAN TOLERATE BROMELIN.
A PLANT ENZYME...
-YES.
-FOUND IN...
PHLOX: AMONG OTHER THINGS,
PINEAPPLE.
HOSHI: PINEAPPLE.
THIS DOESN'T MEAN
IT'S HIS FAVORITE FOOD.
IT'S CLOSE ENOUGH.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ BEEPING ]
-IT'S THEM.
-WHERE ARE THEY?
T'POL: CLOSING FROM ASTERN--
20,000 METERS.
15,000.
MAYWEATHER: SHOULD I TRY
EVASIVE MANEUVERS?
NO. COME ABOUT
AND HOLD OUR POSITION.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
BRIDGE TO THE ARMORY.
GUESS WHO'S BACK.
REED: WE SEE THEM.
BOTH FORWARD CANNONS
ARE CHARGED AND READY.
ARCHER: GET A LOCK AND STAND BY.
T'POL: THEY'VE STOPPED.
11,000 METERS.
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
PUT IT THROUGH.
ARCHER'S VOICE: ...DEFENSELESS.
PREPARE TO SURRENDER
YOUR VESSEL.
YOU ARE DEFENSELESS.
PREPARE TO...
SHUT IT OFF.
YOU ARE DEFENS--
MAYWEATHER: 10,000 METERS.
9,000.
MR. REED...
BOTH CANNONS, FIRE.
I'M READING A FLUCTUATION
IN THEIR SHIELDING,
BUT IT'S MARGINAL.
5,000 METERS.
IS THAT THE BEST WE CAN DO,
LIEUTENANT?!
EVEN IF THESE CANNONS HAD BEEN
INSTALLED AT JUPITER STATION,
THEY WOULDN'T BE ANY MORE
EFFECTIVE THAN THEY ARE NOW.
Archer: What about yesterday?
I saw you blow something up
the size of Mount McKinley.
YES, SIR, BUT THAT WAS DUE
TO AN OVERLOAD.
CAN YOU OVERLOAD THEM AGAIN?
SIR, AFTER THE DAMAGE
FROM THE FIRST TIME,
THE PLASMA RECOIL WILL PROBABLY
KNOCK OUT TWO DECKS.
CAN YOU OVERLOAD THEM AGAIN?!
REED: I BELIEVE SO, BUT...
I'D RATHER KNOCK OUT TWO DECKS
THAN SURRENDER THIS SHIP.
-BUT, SIR...
-HOLD ON A MINUTE.
I THINK THERE'S A WAY
TO HANDLE THE RECOIL.
-How?
-All that excess energy's
got to go somewhere.
-WHY NOT PUT IT TO USE?
-3,000 meters.
IF WE REPOLARIZE THE GRAVITY
PLATING TO ABSORB THE RECOIL,
THEN WE CAN SHUNT THE ENERGY
TO STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY.
SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
THE GRAV-PLATING WASN'T DESIGNED
TO WITHSTAND THAT MUCH FORCE.
WE ALL UNDERSTAND THE RISKS.
GET STARTED.
Reed: Aye, sir.
[ BEEPING ]
MAYWEATHER: 1,000 METERS.
MALCOLM?
STAND BY.
TRIP?
WE'RE READY, SIR.
THEN FIRE!
[ BEEPING ]
THEIR SHIELDS ARE FAILING.
TORPEDOES!
ARCHER: BRIDGE TO THE ARMORY.
EVERYTHING OK DOWN THERE?
TUCKER: WE BLEW OUT
THE PLASMA RELAYS ON B-DECK,
BUT IT'S NOTHING
WE CAN'T TAKE CARE OF.
WHAT ABOUT OUR FRIENDS?
Archer: I have a feeling
THEIR REPAIRS ARE GONNA BE
A LITTLE MORE EXTENSIVE.
Archer: How'd the cannons
hold up?
REED: FAIRLY WELL.
Reed: I'll have them back online
within the hour.
THE AFT CANNON SHOULD BE WORKING
BY THE END OF DAY TOMORROW.
GOOD WORK.
WELL...
I SEE NO REASON FOR US TO GO
BACK TO JUPITER STATION NOW...
DO YOU?
T'POL: NO.
HOSHI: AT LEAST THERE'S
ONE GOOD THING
ABOUT COMING BACK THIS FAR--
WE CAN DROP
ANOTHER SUBSPACE AMPLIFIER.
GET ON IT.
TRAVIS?
RESUME OUR PREVIOUS COURSE.
MAYWEATHER: GLADLY, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
TUCKER: TO OUR
MYSTERIOUS FRIENDS.
I WISH I COULD'VE SEEN
THE LOOKS ON THEIR FACES.
REED: HEAR, HEAR.
[ TUCKER CHUCKLES ]
ARCHER: DON'T GET TOO USED
TO DRINKING ON DUTY...
[ CHUCKLING ]
BUT YOU DID YOUR JOBS
PRETTY DAMN WELL YESTERDAY.
I'D SAY THAT DESERVES
A LITTLE CELEBRATION.
REED: CHEERS.
TUCKER: IF YOU REALLY
WANT TO THANK US,
HOW ABOUT LETTING US
SLEEP IN TOMORROW?
[ LAUGHTER ]
PERMISSION GRANTED.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
HOSHI, WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU?
HOSHI: SORRY TO INTERRUPT,
CAPTAIN.
I HAVE THAT COMPONENT
THAT YOU ASKED FOR.
GREAT.
PUT IT DOWN RIGHT HERE.
HMM.
AS LONG AS WE'VE GOT YOU HERE,
MALCOLM...
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE GONE
TO ANY TROUBLE.
ARCHER: NO, NO TROUBLE AT ALL.
MR. REED,
THE HONOR IS YOURS.
PINEAPPLE!
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
HOW ON EARTH DID YOU KNOW?
HOSHI: WE HAVE OUR SOURCES.