REED: YOU HAVE
A 10-SECOND FIRING WINDOW.
READY?
READY.
GO.
TIME.
ANY BETTER?
YOUR HIT-TO-MISS RATIO
IS STILL BELOW 50%.
IF THOSE HAD
BEEN LIVE ROUNDS,
YOU'D HAVE BLOWN OUT
TWO OR THREE BULKHEADS.
I NEVER HAD THIS MUCH TROUBLE
WITH THE EM-33.
THIS IS AN ENTIRELY NEW WEAPON.
UNLIKE THE EM-33,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO COMPENSATE
FOR PARTICLE DRIFT.
JUST POINT STRAIGHT
AT THE TARGET.
AND TRY AND KEEP
YOUR SHOULDERS RELAXED.
IT'S HARD TO AIM ACCURATELY
WHEN YOU'RE TENSE.
[ SIGHS ]
[ COUGHS ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, FINE.
YOU'LL GET THE HANG OF IT.
LET'S TRY FOR 20 SECONDS
THIS TIME.
[ ENGINES WHOOSH ]
I THOUGHT WE WERE STAYING
AT WARP FOR THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
OH, WE'RE APPROACHING
A GAS GIANT -- CLASS-9.
SO MUCH FOR TARGET PRACTICE.
WE'LL PICK IT UP TOMORROW.
MAN: ♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
THE PROBE'S ENTERED
THE OUTER ATMOSPHERE.
ARCHER: CAN WE CLEAN UP
THE SIGNAL?
HOSHI: I'M TRYING, SIR.
THERE'S A LOT
OF E.M. INTERFERENCE
THAT SOUNDS VERY STRANGE.
T'POL: INTENSE MAGNETIC FIELDS
OFTEN CREATE UNIQUE WAVEFORMS.
ARCHER: LET'S HEAR THEM.
[ HOWLING ]
TRAVIS: SIREN CALLS.
THAT'S WHAT WE CALLED THEM
WHEN I WAS A KID.
MY DAD WOULD PUT THEM
THROUGH THE SPEAKERS
WHENEVER WE FLEW BY
A GAS GIANT.
IT GAVE ME NIGHTMARES SOMETIMES.
T'POL: OTHER THAN KEEPING
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER UP AT NIGHT,
I'M NOT SURE WHAT WE EXPECT
TO ACCOMPLISH HERE.
THERE ARE FOUR GAS GIANTS
IN YOUR OWN SOLAR SYSTEM.
ARCHER: NONE OF THEM
ARE CLASS-9.
I THINK THIS ONE'S
WORTH A CLOSER LOOK.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
I'M READING AN ANOMALOUS
POWER SIGNATURE
IN THE LOWER ATMOSPHERE...
AND SEVERAL BIO-SIGNS.
ARCHER: GET THE PROBE CLOSER.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
[ SNEEZES ]
WE CAN TRAVEL FASTER
THAN THE SPEED OF LIGHT.
YOU'D THINK WE COULD FIND
A CURE FOR THE COMMON COLD.
PHLOX: YOU SHOULD BE GRATEFUL
A HUMAN COLD IS SO MILD.
I ONCE HAD A PATIENT
WITH THE KAMARAAZITE FLU.
HE SNEEZED SO VIOLENTLY,
HE NEARLY REGURGITATED
HIS PINEAL GLAND.
I DON'T SEE HOW I COULD
ACTUALLY CATCH A COLD
ON A HERMETICALLY SEALED
STARSHIP.
OH, YOU MAY HAVE
PICKED UP A VIRUS
FROM A PIECE OF EQUIPMENT.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN LURKING
INSIDE A SEALED CONTAINER.
I DID OPEN A CASE
OF PLASMA COOLANT.
WELL, WHOEVER PACKED THAT CASE
WAS PROBABLY NURSING A COLD.
BUT THAT WAS BACK AT SPACEDOCK
FIVE MONTHS AGO.
YOU UNDERESTIMATE THE TENACITY
OF A VIRUS, LIEUTENANT.
IT CAN LAY DORMANT FOR MONTHS,
ADAPT TO WHATEVER ENVIRONMENT
IT FINDS ITSELF IN, HMM?
THIS SHOULD EASE THE SYMPTOMS.
BUT THE ONLY CURE I KNOW OF
INVOLVES BED REST.
OH, NO, THAT'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
THE CAPTAIN WANTS ME ON THE TEAM
INVESTIGATING THAT SHIPWRECK.
AH.
WELL, YOU WON'T BE CONTAGIOUS
INSIDE AN ENVIRONMENT SUIT.
JUST TRY NOT TO SNEEZE
IN YOUR HELMET.
[ SIGHS ]
I'LL DO MY BEST.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
HOSHI.
DO YOU HAVE A MINUTE, SIR?
OF COURSE.
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
THAT SHIPWRECK.
WE HAVE NO IDEA WHAT TYPE
OF LIFE-FORMS
WE'LL FIND
ON THAT ALIEN VESSEL,
AND THERE'S A LOT OF
INTERFERENCE IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
ARE YOU SURE THE AWAY TEAM
WON'T NEED A TRANSLATOR?
ARCHER: THEY HAVE THEIR U.T.s.
AND WE'LL TRY TO KEEP
AN OPEN COM LINK.
WHAT ABOUT THE LANGUAGE ON THE
CONTROL PANELS, THE HATCHES?
THEY MIGHT NEED SOMEONE TO HELP
THEM FIND THEIR WAY AROUND.
ARE YOU TRYING TO
TELL ME SOMETHING?
I REALIZE THAT
I HAVEN'T ALWAYS BEEN
THE FIRST ONE IN LINE
TO VOLUNTEER
FOR THIS TYPE OF MISSION,
BUT I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I AM PREPARED TO GO.
TOOK A WHILE, BUT I THINK
I FINALLY GOT MY SPACE LEGS.
I NEVER DOUBTED
THAT YOU'D FIND THEM.
YOUR TIMING COULDN'T BE BETTER.
T'POL JUST ASKED ME
TO ASSIGN YOU TO THE TEAM.
YOU'D BETTER GET
TO THE LAUNCH BAY
BEFORE THEY LEAVE WITHOUT YOU.
AYE, SIR.
T'POL: I THOUGHT YOU WERE
ACQUAINTED WITH THE
ENVIRONMENTAL SUIT.
HOSHI: I AM.
I'M JUST BRUSHING UP
ON THE BACKUP SYSTEMS.
I WOULDN'T WANT THE
EMERGENCY OXYGEN TO FAIL
DURING A HULL BREACH.
REED: TRUST ME, ENSIGN.
IF THERE'S A HULL BREACH,
THE PRESSURE WILL CRUSH YOU
INTO SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS BIG.
T'POL: I REQUESTED YOU FOR YOUR
SKILLS AS A TRANSLATOR,
BUT IF YOU'RE UNCOMFORTABLE --
I'M PERFECTLY COMFORTABLE.
I USED TO FIND THE SUITS
A LITTLE CLAUSTROPHOBIC,
BUT I'M GETTING USED TO THEM.
I'LL SEE YOU IN THE SHUTTLEPOD.
IT'S 100 KILOMETERS BELOW US.
STILL DESCENDING.
GRAVITY'S PULLING IT
DEEPER INTO THE ATMOSPHERE.
AT THEIR CURRENT ALTITUDE,
THE PRESSURE IS 15,000 GSC.
WELL, THAT'S WELL WITHIN
OUR HULL TOLERANCE.
T'POL: FOR THE MOMENT,
BUT AT THE RATE
THAT VESSEL IS SINKING,
WE'LL HAVE AN HOUR AT MOST.
YOU SOUND UNCOMFORTABLE,
SUBCOMMANDER.
I'M MERELY STATING FACTS.
REED: WE'LL BE ON OUR WAY BACK
WELL BEFORE WE'RE IN ANY DANGER.
I, FOR ONE, HAVE NO INTEREST
IN IMPLODING
A VALUABLE SHUTTLEPOD.
OR THREE VALUABLE OFFICERS.
[ RUMBLING, ALARM BEEPS ]
WE'VE ENTERED
AN EDDY OF LIQUID HELIUM.
WE'RE CLEAR.
THAT WASN'T SO BAD.
100 METERS.
IS THAT A HATCH
ON THE PORT SIDE?
I SEE IT.
50 METERS.
T'POL: 40.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S JUST A PROXIMITY ALARM.
20 METERS.
T'POL: 10.
[RUMBLING]
ENGAGING DOCKING INTERFACE.
NITROGEN-OXYGEN ATMOSPHERE.
CARBON-DIOXIDE LEVELS ARE HIGH,
BUT NOTHING'S TOXIC.
IT'S BREATHABLE.
YOU FIRST.
[ SNIFFS ]
PERHAPS WE SHOULD LEAVE
THE HELMETS ON.
-WHAT IS IT?
-[ COUGHS ]
YOU CAN'T SMELL THAT?
NO. THIS DAMN COLD.
COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS.
YOU TWO MIGHT WANT TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
IT SAYS "DECK TWO, RED SECTOR."
WHAT LANGUAGE?
KLINGON.
HOSHI: I THOUGHT
YOU KNEW KLINGON SHIPS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU RECOGNIZE
THIS ONE FROM THE OUTSIDE?
T'POL: THERE ARE MANY
CLASSES OF SHIPS.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH ALL OF THEM.
REED: SO, I'M ASSUMING
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
KLINGONS ARE ONBOARD.
T'POL: I'M READING THREE BIO-
SIGNS, THAT WAY, ALL VERY WEAK.
HOSHI: HOW WEAK?
T'POL: THEY'RE STILL ALIVE.
WE SHOULD LEAVE BEFORE THEY
REGAIN CONSCIOUSNESS.
AND WHAT IF THEY DON'T?
THE ATMOSPHERE IS GOING
TO CRUSH THEIR SHIP
LIKE AN EGGSHELL PRETTY SOON.
SHOULDN'T WE TRY TO HELP THEM?
THEY DON'T WANT OUR HELP.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
THEY'RE KLINGONS.
TO DIE AT THEIR POST ASSURES
THEM A PATH TO THE AFTERLIFE.
IF WE RESCUE THEM,
THEY'D BE DISHONORED.
REED: WELL, I, FOR ONE,
DON'T INTEND
TO JUST FLY OFF
AND LET THESE PEOPLE DIE,
HONORABLE DEATHS OR NOT.
YOUR COMPASSION IS ADMIRABLE,
BUT MISGUIDED.
IF THEY AWAKE AND FIND US
ON THEIR SHIP, THEY'LL KILL US.
Archer: How many are there?
T'POL: THREE ON THE BRIDGE.
BUT I'M DETECTING AT LEAST
NINE MORE BIO-SIGNS ONBOARD.
Archer: You can't tell
what happened to them?
I'M DETECTING RESIDUAL AMOUNTS
of a carbon-dioxide-based
neurotoxin,
but it seems to have dissipated.
There's not enough to affect us.
STAND BY.
HOW LONG IS THE POD'S HULL
GOING TO HOLD UP?
AT THEIR PRESENT RATE
OF DESCENT...
HALF-HOUR, GIVE OR TAKE.
T'POL.
T'Pol: Yes, Captain.
YOU'VE GOT 20 MINUTES
TO SEE IF YOU CAN DO ANYTHING
FOR THAT CREW.
THEN I WANT YOU OUT OF THERE.
Archer: Understood?
I DON'T BELIEVE THERE'S ANYTHING
WE CAN DO IN 20 MINUTES.
I SUGGEST WE LEAVE NOW.
Archer: You have
a margin of safety...
[ Static ]
CAPTAIN?
T'POL TO ENTERPRISE.
[ Static ]
REED: DAMN INTERFERENCE.
T'POL: OR WE'VE DROPPED
OUT OF COM RANGE.
HOSHI: WE STILL HAVE 20 MINUTES.
T'POL: IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE
TO PLACE OURSELVES AT RISK
WHEN THEY'D RATHER DIE.
REED: THERE MUST BE
SOMETHING WE CAN DO.
MAYBE THEY HAVE A DISTRESS
BEACON WE CAN ACTIVATE.
T'POL: I DOUBT YOU'LL FIND ONE.
KLINGONS DON'T CALL FOR HELP.
HOSHI: WHAT IF WE CARRY SOME
OF THEM INTO THE POD?
WE COULD SAVE THREE OR FOUR.
AND IF THEY WAKE UP ON THE TRIP
BACK TO ENTERPRISE?
[ DOOR OPENS ]
AAH!
UGH!
OHH.
[ ENGINES WHOOSH ]
[ BEEP ]
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S OUR SHUTTLEPOD TAKING OFF.
TRY IT NOW.
ARCHER TO T'POL.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
[ Static ]
THEY'RE BACK IN COM RANGE.
TRAVIS: CAPTAIN.
SHUTTLEPOD 1, RESPOND.
SIR, THEY'RE HEADING
INTO OPEN SPACE.
TRIP: I'M PICKING UP SOMETHING.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
SOUNDS LIKE KLINGON.
I'LL TRY TO TIE IN THE U.T.
KLINGON: ...IN RANGE. RESPOND.
WE'VE BEEN ATTACKED
BY AN UNKNOWN SHIP,
DESIGNATION ENTERPRISE NX-01.
ANY WARSHIPS IN RANGE, RESPOND.
ARCHER: SET A PURSUIT COURSE.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
BRING THE GRAPPLER ONLINE.
TRIP: WE'VE GOT IT.
BRIDGE TO SECURITY.
SEND A TEAM TO LAUNCH BAY 1.
TRIP.
THE BRIDGE IS YOURS, TRAVIS.
TRAVIS: YES, SIR.
[ GRUNTING ]
EVERYBODY ALL RIGHT?
ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
Travis: Mayweather.
HAVE YOU STILL
GOT A FIX ON THE SHIPWRECK?
Travis: Yes, sir.
TRANSFER THE COORDINATES
TO THE LAUNCH BAY.
I'M GOING BACK
FOR THE BOARDING PARTY.
Travis: Sir, the alien ship
sunk another 2,000 meters.
It's below
the shuttle's safety limits.
THEN POLARIZE THE HULL PLATING.
WE'LL TAKE ENTERPRISE DOWN.
REED: THERE'S GOT TO BE
SOME WAY OFF THIS SHIP.
HOSHI: WHAT ABOUT ESCAPE PODS?
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT
THE STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY
OF KLINGON ESCAPE PODS.
MY GUESS IS WE'RE
BETTER OFF IN HERE.
T'POL: IT'S IRRELEVANT,
LIEUTENANT.
KLINGONS DON'T USE ESCAPE PODS.
IT WOULD BE CONSIDERED
AN ACT OF COWARDICE
TO ABANDON SHIP.
HOSHI: MAYBE WE CAN USE
THEIR COM SYSTEM
TO CONTACT ENTERPRISE.
T'POL: I DOUBT THEIR COM
WILL PENETRATE THE E.M. FIELD
ANY BETTER THAN OUR OWN.
IF WE CAN ACCESS
THEIR HELM CONTROLS,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO PUT THIS
VESSEL INTO A STABLE ORBIT.
REED: I HAVEN'T HAD MUCH
EXPERIENCE AT PILOTING
KLINGON SHIPS.
WE HAVE NO OTHER CHOICE.
[ RUMBLING, CREAKING ]
START TRANSLATING
THOSE CONSOLES.
LOOK FOR ANYTHING MARKED
PROPULSION, HELM, NAVIGATION.
I'LL TRY, BUT READING KLINGON
IS A LOT DIFFERENT
THAN SPEAKING IT.
WE COULD ALWAYS TRY WAKING
ONE OF THEM TO HELP US.
ALL RIGHT.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
"PLASMA CONTAINMENT," MAYBE?
T'POL: YOU'RE CERTAIN?
HOSHI: "CONTAINMENT."
I'M CERTAIN.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
SOMETHING THEY CALL
PHOTON TORPEDOES?
REED: PHOTON TORPEDOES?
I NEVER HEARD OF ANYTHING
LIKE THAT. WHAT ELSE?
THIS ALL LOOKS
LIKE WEAPONS SYSTEMS --
TORPEDOES, TACTICAL SENSORS,
DISRUPTOR ARRAYS.
WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE?
HOSHI: I RECOGNIZE
"PRESSURE."
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
THAT CAN MEAN
"WALL" OR "BARRIER."
T'POL: OR "HULL"?
HOSHI: MAYBE.
REED: IF I'M READING THIS
CORRECTLY, WE'VE GOT
A FEW HOURS AT MOST.
THE HULL INTEGRITY
IS FAILING.
T'POL: THEN WE BETTER HURRY.
THIS APPEARS
TO BE THE HELM STATION.
HOSHI: I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
"IMPULSE DRIVE."
REED: GOOD WORK, HOSHI.
[ BEEPING ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
REED: HOSHI?
HOSHI: IT SAYS THE
PRESSURE'S FAILING
IN THE [SPEAKS KLINGON]
"FUSION MANIFOLD."
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS?
TO QUOTE OUR VERY OWN
MR. TUCKER,
IT MEANS WE'RE
DEAD IN THE WATER.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Archer: Archer
to boarding party.
Come in.
HOSHI: WE READ YOU, CAPTAIN.
HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
Hoshi: We're doing okay, sir.
It's nice to hear your voice.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
T'POL: WE'VE BEEN ATTEMPTING
TO RESTART THEIR ENGINES,
BUT THEY APPEAR
TO BE OFFLINE.
Archer: Don't worry about it.
We're coming to get you.
TRAVIS, HOW MUCH FARTHER?
10,000 METERS,
BUT I'M HAVING A HARD TIME
GETTING A FIX ON THEM.
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE.
IS OUR PROBE STILL WORKING?
TRIP: BARELY.
TRY USING IT TO TRIANGULATE
THEIR POSITION.
THE PROBE'S GONE.
[ CREAKING ]
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
SIR, EXTERNAL PRESSURE'S
AT MAXIMUM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
I'M AFRAID WE'VE GOT A LITTLE
HITCH IN OUR RESCUE PLAN.
THE HULL PLATING IS FAILING.
WE'LL BE BACK FOR YOU
AS SOON AS WE CAN.
Archer: [ Distorted ] In the
meantime, just sit tight.
See what you can do
about getting those
engines back online.
HOSHI: CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE BREAKING UP.
CAPTAIN?
RELEASE ME!
COWARDS!
LET ME DIE ON MY FEET!
PHLOX: T'POL WAS RIGHT.
THERE'S A NEUROTOXIN
IN HER BLOODSTREAM.
UNTREATED, IT COULD KILL HER
WITHIN A DAY OR TWO.
ARCHER: CAN YOU DO ANYTHING?
PHLOX: I'M WORKING ON IT.
TRIP: T'POL SAID THE KLINGONS
WERE UNCONSCIOUS.
WHY IS THIS ONE SO LIVELY?
PHLOX: SHE'S SHOWING THE EFFECTS
OF HYPOTHERMIA.
MY GUESS IS SHE TOOK REFUGE
IN A LOW-TEMPERATURE
ENVIRONMENT ABOARD HER SHIP.
THE COLD WOULD HAVE DELAYED
THE EFFECTS OF THE TOXIN.
KLINGON: I DEMAND
TO SPEAK TO YOUR CAPTAIN.
TRIP: YOU KNOW, I READ IF THEY
SENSE A LEADER'S WEAK,
THEY'LL TRY TO KILL HIM
AND TAKE COMMAND.
I'M THE CAPTAIN.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN
YOUR KIND BEFORE,
BUT YOU HAVE MADE AN ENEMY
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
FROM WHAT I'VE NOTICED,
THAT'S NOT HARD TO DO.
YOU STRANDED THREE
OF MY PEOPLE DOWN THERE.
YOU RAIDED MY VESSEL,
INFECTED MY CREW!
WE DIDN'T INFECT ANYONE.
WE BOARDED YOUR SHIP
TO TRY AND HELP.
LIAR.
LOOK, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR CREW,
BUT WE HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
NOW YOUR VESSEL IS SINKING
DEEPER INTO THE ATMOSPHERE.
UNLESS WE DO SOMETHING,
IT'LL BE DESTROYED.
BETTER THAT THAN LET IT FALL
INTO YOUR HANDS.
I'VE GOT THREE VERY CAPABLE
PEOPLE ON YOUR SHIP.
LET THEM HELP.
IF YOU TELL THEM HOW TO GET
THE ENGINES RUNNING,
THEY CAN FLY IT OUT OF THERE.
AND FLY IT WHERE?
BACK TO YOUR WORLD
TO STEAL OUR SECRETS?
NO.
WHEN OUR BIRDS-OF-PREY ARRIVE,
YOUR SHIP WILL BE DESTROYED.
REMIND ME TO STOP
TRYING TO HELP PEOPLE.
TRAVIS: I FOUND THESE SCHEMATICS
IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
IT'S A RAPTOR-CLASS
SCOUT VESSEL.
HOW LONG WILL IT
LAST DOWN THERE?
ITS HULL'S AT LEAST
TWICE AS THICK AS OURS,
REINFORCED WITH SOME KIND
OF COHERENT MOLECULAR ALLOY.
YEAH, IT'S
A TOUGH LITTLE SHIP,
BUT IT CAN'T HOLD UP
UNDER THAT PRESSURE FOREVER.
WHAT IF WE USE
DURATANIUM BRACES
TO REINFORCE A SHUTTLEPOD?
IT WON'T LOOK PRETTY, BUT...
IT MIGHT HOLD UP LONG ENOUGH
FOR US TO GET OUR PEOPLE OUT.
OUR ONLY OTHER OPTION
IS FOR T'POL AND MALCOLM
TO FIX A BROKEN-DOWN
KLINGON SHIP
AND FLY IT OUT THEMSELVES.
I DON'T THINK WE'RE GONNA
GET ANY HELP
FROM OUR GUEST IN SICK BAY.
GET STARTED ON THOSE BRACES.
KEEP AN EYE OUT
FOR ANY KLINGON SHIPS
COMING THIS WAY.
AYE, SIR.
AH, THE ONE TIME WE NEED
OUR CHIEF ENGINEER
IS THE ONE TIME
WE LEAVE HIM BEHIND.
COME LOOK AT THIS.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
...Q'TAHL-CLASS PLANET.
WE DESTROYED THEIR SHIP,
BUT WE'VE SUSTAINED DAMAGE
IN OUR PORT FUSION INJECTOR.
WE'VE DESCENDED
INTO THE OUTER ATMOSPHERE
OF A Q'TAHL-CLASS PLANET
TO MAKE REPAIRS,
IN CASE THERE ARE OTHER
XARANTINE SHIPS IN THE AREA.
[ COUGHING ]
MY CREW IS FALLING ILL,
AND I HAVE BEEN UNABLE
TO DETERMINE WHY.
IF WE HAD DIED
WHEN THE XARANTINE ATTACKED,
OUR HONOR WOULD BE SECURE,
BUT TO FALL VICTIM
TO SOME DISEASE,
TO BE CRUSHED INTO NOTHING
IN THE DEPTHS
OF THIS MISERABLE PLANET --
[ COUGHING ]
REED: SOUNDS LIKE WE NEED TO
FIND THE PORT FUSION INJECTOR.
WAIT, I SAW THAT SOMEWHERE.
HOSHI: HERE. ONE DECK BELOW US.
IT'S IN THE REACTOR PIT.
REED: REACTOR PIT?
COULD THAT BE ENGINEERING?
HOSHI: COULD BE.
REED: THIS ONE?
HOSHI: NO.
THAT SAYS SOMETHING
ABOUT PLASMA INDUCTION.
HERE IT IS.
"PORT FUSION INJECTOR."
[ BOTH GRUNT ]
ARCHER: I THINK I MIGHT HAVE
MADE A TACTICAL ERROR
DEALING WITH THE KLINGON WOMAN.
I ASKED HER FOR HELP.
SHE COULD SEE THAT
AS A SIGN OF WEAKNESS.
TRIP: YOU BEEN BONING UP
ON YOUR KLINGON PSYCHOLOGY?
ARCHER: WE'VE RUN
INTO THEM THREE TIMES,
AND EVERY TIME THEY'VE
WANTED TO DESTROY US.
I'D LOVE TO FIGURE OUT WHY.
TRIP: YOU KNOW, MAYBE
THE BEST THING IS JUST
TO STEER CLEAR OF THEM.
ARCHER: THAT MIGHT
NOT BE SO EASY,
BUT WE COULD USE
THEIR HELP RIGHT NOW.
IF WE COULD REESTABLISH
A COM SIGNAL
WITH T'POL AND THE OTHERS,
THE KLINGON WOMAN COULD PROBABLY
TALK THEM THROUGH THE REPAIRS,
BUT SHE'S GOT A THOUSAND
GENERATIONS OF INSTINCT
TELLING HER NOT TO TRUST ME.
TRIP: WELL, MAYBE IT'S TIME
YOU STARTED THINKING
LIKE A KLINGON.
AAH!
HOSHI: ARE YOU OKAY?
REED: YES!
I SEEM TO BE GETTING
A LITTLE LIGHTHEADED.
MUST BE THE HEAT.
T'POL: YOU'RE DEHYDRATED.
YOU NEED SOME WATER.
HOSHI: I SAW A GALLEY
ON THE SCHEMATICS --
DECK FOUR, BLUE SECTOR.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN FIND.
T'POL: YOU SHOULDN'T GO ALONE.
WATCH YOURSELVES.
UGH.
T'POL: IT'S CALLED GAGH.
IT'S A KLINGON DELICACY,
BUT ONLY WHEN THEY'RE ALIVE.
HOSHI: THEY LOOK LIKE WORMS.
THEY ARE WORMS.
[ GASPS ]
[ RATTLING ]
[ ROARING ]
[ GASPS ]
T'POL: TARGS.
KLINGONS PREFER THEIR FOOD
FRESHLY SLAUGHTERED.
[ PANTING ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
HOSHI: I PROMISED MYSELF
I WOULDN'T DO THIS.
YOU'RE IN A DANGEROUS SITUATION
IN AN ALIEN ENVIRONMENT.
YOUR ANXIETY IS UNDERSTANDABLE.
[ SIGHS ]
DON'T YOU MEAN "FOR A HUMAN"?
T'POL: YOU CAN'T DENY
YOUR NATURE.
HOSHI: THIS MAY
SOUND STRANGE.
BUT I ENVY YOU SOMETIMES.
I KNOW.
ANOTHER...PESKY HUMAN EMOTION.
BUT THERE ARE TIMES
I WISH I COULD
JUST IGNORE MY FEELINGS,
BURY THEM THE WAY VULCANS DO.
TAKE MY HAND.
EXCUSE ME?
MY HAND.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
THINK OF YOURSELF
ON A TURBULENT OCEAN.
YOU HAVE THE POWER
TO CONTROL THE WAVES.
WHATEVER IT IS YOU'RE TRYING
TO DO, IT'S NOT WORKING.
FOCUS.
THE WAVES ARE SUBSIDING.
THE WATER IS GROWING STILL.
YOU'RE IN CONTROL.
THAT WAS...AMAZING.
WHEN WE RETURN TO THE SHIP,
I'LL TEACH YOU HOW TO DO IT
ON YOUR OWN.
THANKS.
[ RATTLING ]
T'POL: LIEUTENANT REED, REPORT.
REED: THE HULL PRESSURE'S
APPROACHING CRITICAL!
THIS SHIP'S ABOUT TO BE CRUSHED!
IT'LL WORK.
IF YOU'RE WRONG,
IT COULD DESTROY THE SHIP.
[ CREAKING ]
LOOK, EVEN WITH HOSHI'S HELP,
IT COULD TAKE HOURS JUST TO FIND
THE FUSION INJECTOR IN HERE.
WE'RE OUT OF TIME.
I SAY WE TRY THE WEAPONS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW YOU CAN EVEN
ACCESS THE TACTICAL SYSTEMS?
IF THERE'S ONE THING
ONBOARD THIS SHIP
I OUGHT TO BE ABLE TO FIGURE
OUT, IT'S THE TORPEDOES.
TRIP: I'D LIKE TO RUN
ONE MORE STRUCTURAL DIAGNOSTIC
BEFORE YOU LAUNCH.
QAPLA'.
BEG YOUR PARDON?
SUCCESS.
I DECIDED TO TAKE YOUR ADVICE
ABOUT THINKING LIKE A KLINGON.
THE VULCAN DATABASE HAS
ABOUT 900 PAGES ON THEM.
TRIP: LEARN ANYTHING?
PLENTY.
THEY'RE DRIVEN BY
A WARRIOR MENTALITY.
THEY TEND TO VIEW ANYONE
THEY MEET AS A POTENTIAL ENEMY.
THAT MAY EXPLAIN WHY
OUR GUEST IS SO IRRITABLE.
THEY ALSO HAVE
A STRONG SENSE OF DUTY.
UH...
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
"DEATH BEFORE DISHONOR."
FINISH UP THAT DIAGNOSTIC.
I'LL BE IN SICK BAY.
GONNA GO PUT
YOUR HOMEWORK TO USE?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
PHLOX: PLEASE RELAX.
IF YOU STRAIN
AGAINST THE STRAPS,
YOU MIGHT HURT YOURSELF.
WHAT'S THAT?
IS THAT WHAT YOU USED
AGAINST MY CREW?
DR. PHLOX HAS DEVELOPED
AN ANTIDOTE
TO THE NEUROTOXIN
IN YOUR SYSTEM.
IS THIS HOW YOU PLAN
TO GAIN MY TRUST?
FIRST POISON ME,
THEN MIRACULOUSLY CURE ME?
HAVE YOU HAD A DRINK LATELY?
WHAT?
ARCHER: THE BIO-AGENT
THAT AFFECTED YOU AND YOUR CREW
WAS CONSUMED,
APPARENTLY IN ALCOHOL.
PHLOX: SPECIFICALLY, THE TOXIN
WAS BONDED TO A MOLECULE
UNIQUE TO XARANTINE ALE.
THERE WAS A RAID.
ARCHER: YES?
I CAN UNDERSTAND YOUR NOT
WANTING TO TALK ABOUT IT
IF THE RAID WENT BADLY FOR YOU.
THE XARANTINES
ARE NO MATCH FOR US!
WE ATTACKED THEIR OUTPOST
AND TOOK WHAT WE WANTED.
AND THAT INCLUDED
SOME XARANTINE ALE?
DID YOUR WHOLE CREW DRINK IT?
THE TRIUMPH BELONGED TO ALL.
I'LL TAKE THAT AS A YES.
IT WAS THAT ALE
THAT INFECTED YOU, NOT US.
THINK ABOUT IT.
WHEN DID YOUR CREW
START GETTING SICK?
WAS IT RIGHT AFTER THE RAID?
AFTER YOU CELEBRATED
YOUR VICTORY?
THIS IS A TRICK.
ARCHER: IS IT?
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
BETTER OR WORSE
SINCE THE INJECTION?
WE CAN MAKE ENOUGH OF THIS
FOR YOUR ENTIRE CREW
IF IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
[ SIGHS ]
WHAT IF THIS ISN'T A TRICK?
WHAT IF WE'RE TELLING YOU
THE TRUTH?
YOU'D BE LETTING YOUR CREW DIE
A VERY DISHONORABLE DEATH
WHEN YOU COULD HAVE
SAVED THEM.
CAN YOU LIVE WITH THAT?
HOSHI: 1,000 METERS.
2,000.
3,000.
NO EFFECT!
WE'RE STILL SINKING.
THE SHOCK WAVE DISSIPATED
BEFORE IT REACHED US.
REED: WE NEED TO DETONATE ONE
CLOSER NEXT TIME.
[ CREAKING ]
THE SHIP'S HULL IS UNDER
ENOUGH PRESSURE ALREADY.
IF YOU DETONATE
A TORPEDO TOO CLOSE --
REED: AND IF I DON'T?
WE NEED TO GENERATE
A LARGE ENOUGH SHOCK WAVE
TO PUSH US INTO A HIGHER ORBIT.
TO DO THAT, THE BLAST HAS TO BE
BIG, AND IT HAS TO BE CLOSE.
YOU HEARD THE SUBCOMMANDER.
LOAD TWO THIS TIME.
SENSOR RESOLUTION'S
DROPPING OFF.
THIS WAS YOUR PLAN?
TO GROPE IN THE DARKNESS
AND HOPE TO STUMBLE
ACROSS MY SHIP?
THAT'S HOW WE FOUND IT
THE FIRST TIME.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
KLINGON: WHAT WAS THAT?
WEAPONS FIRE.
KLINGON: WHERE?
BEARING 297 MARK 261,
DOWN ABOUT TWO KILOMETERS.
REED: DID IT WORK?
HOSHI: WE'VE MOVED UP,
BUT ONLY 200 METERS.
THAT'S ALL?
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
A COMPARTMENT JUST COLLAPSED --
DECK THREE, GREEN SECTOR.
THIS WHOLE DAMN SHIP'S
COMING APART.
HOW MANY TORPEDOES
DO WE HAVE LEFT?
HOSHI: SIX.
REED: LOAD TWO MORE.
HOSHI: IT WON'T BE ENOUGH.
REED: LOAD THE WEAPONS.
WE ALREADY TRIED --
IT DIDN'T WORK.
REED: ENSIGN.
T'POL: SHE'S RIGHT.
WE'LL NEVER REACH
A SAFE ALTITUDE
CLIMBING A FEW HUNDRED METERS
AT A TIME.
THE LONGER WE STAND
AROUND ARGUING,
THE MORE GROUND WE LOSE.
FIRE THEM ALL.
WHAT IF WE DETONATED
ALL THE TORPEDOES AT ONCE?
WE MAY GAIN ENOUGH ALTITUDE,
BUT I DOUBT WE'D MAKE IT
IN ONE PIECE.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I'M WILLING
TO TAKE THE CHANCE.
WE'LL DETONATE AT 800 METERS.
I WAS THINKING MORE LIKE 500.
LOOK, I DIDN'T COME
ALL THIS WAY
TO GET CRUSHED IN THE ATMOSPHERE
OF SOME ANONYMOUS GAS GIANT.
LOADING PORTS ONE THROUGH SIX.
BRACE YOURSELVES.
TORPEDOES ARMED.
UGH!
OH!
KLINGON: WHAT IS IT?
ANOTHER EXPLOSION.
THERE'S A SHOCK WAVE THIS TIME.
HANG ON!
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
T'POL.
Archer: What have you
been shooting at?
WE USED THE SHOCK WAVES
TO GAIN SOME ALTITUDE,
BUT IT'S ONLY TEMPORARY.
WE'LL START SINKING AGAIN
UNLESS WE CAN COME UP WITH A WAY
TO GET THIS SHIP OUT OF HERE.
I BROUGHT SOMEONE WHO SHOULD
BE ABLE TO HELP DO JUST THAT.
WE'RE DOCKING NOW.
[ BEEP ]
I BELIEVE YOU'VE
ALL MET OFFICER BU'KAH.
WHAT'S THE STATUS
OF THEIR ENGINES?
THE KLINGON CREW
MADE MOST OF
THE NECESSARY REPAIRS
BEFORE THEY WERE OVERCOME,
BUT THE PORT FUSION INJECTOR
IS STILL DAMAGED.
I WILL TEND TO MY OWN SHIP.
I DIDN'T BRING YOU DOWN HERE
JUST SO YOU COULD DIE
WITH YOUR SHIPMATES.
MY CREW RISKED THEIR LIVES
TO GET THIS SHIP OUT OF DANGER.
I DON'T INTEND TO LEAVE
UNTIL THE JOB IS FINISHED.
SIR, THERE ARE TWO SHIPS
APPROACHING AT HIGH WARP.
I THINK THEY'RE KLINGON.
ARCHER: HOW LONG TILL
THEY GET HERE?
16 MINUTES.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
IT'S THE CAPTAIN.
ON SCREEN.
THIS IS KLINGON RAPTOR SOMRAW,
HAILING ENTERPRISE.
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO DISEMBARK FOUR PASSENGERS.
WELL, I DON'T SEE WHY NOT.
I KEPT YOUR SEAT WARM FOR YOU.
THANKS.
GET READY
TO BREAK ORBIT, TRAVIS.
I THINK WE'VE HAD ABOUT ENOUGH
OF THIS PLACE.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
IT'S THE RAPTOR, SIR.
THEY'RE HAILING US.
TRIP: CALLING TO SAY THANKS?
I DOUBT IT.
PUT IT THROUGH.
ARCHER: WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
PREPARE TO SURRENDER
YOUR VESSEL.
MAYBE YOUR ENGINEER
NEGLECTED TO TELL YOU,
BUT, UH, WE JUST SAVED YOU
AND YOUR CREW.
YOU VIOLATED OUR SHIP,
ACCESSED OUR WEAPONS.
IT WAS EITHER THAT OR STAND BY
AND WATCH YOU GET CRUSHED.
DISRUPTORS!
TRIP: THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
YOU WOULDN'T LAST 10 SECONDS
IN A BATTLE WITH US.
YOU'VE GOT
MULTIPLE HULL BREACHES,
YOUR SHIELDS ARE DOWN,
AND FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
YOU'RE FRESH OUT OF TORPEDOES.
IF I WERE YOU, I'D TAKE
WHAT LITTLE HONOR I HAD LEFT
AND GO HOME.
FIRE ONE SHOT,
AND I'LL BLAST YOU RIGHT BACK
TO WHERE WE FOUND YOU.
[ GROWLS ]
TRAVIS: THEY'RE MOVING OFF.
GET US OUT OF HERE
BEFORE THEIR FRIENDS SHOW UP.
[ SIGHS ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
REED: IS SOMEONE GONNA GET THAT?
HOSHI: YOU'RE CLOSER.
[ SIGHS ]
T'POL.
Phlox: This is Dr. Phlox.
You'll be happy to know
that you're now free
of any microbes or parasites.
Your captivity in decon is over.
REED: ARE YOU SURE, DOCTOR?
WHO KNOWS WHAT WAS LIVING
ON THAT SHIP?
HOSHI: WHAT IF WE
PICKED UP SOMETHING
YOUR SCANS CAN'T DETECT?
Phlox: Well, I'm
quite sure you didn't.
I've run every possible test.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD RUN THEM AGAIN,
DOCTOR.
I BELIEVE I'M DEVELOPING
A SLIGHT...HEADACHE.
Phlox: Of course,
if you insist.
I wouldn't want
to miss anything.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
[ SIGHING ]
REED: THAT SHOULD BUY US AT
LEAST ANOTHER HALF AN HOUR.
[ BOTH CHUCKLING ]
OH, I COULD STAY IN HERE
ALL DAY.
MMM.
REED: WENT TO A SPA
ONCE IN MEXICO.
THE MOST RELAXING
PLACE I'VE EVER BEEN,
BUT IT DOESN'T
COMPARE TO THIS.
OH, IT CERTAINLY FEELS
NICE TO BE CLEAN AGAIN.
T'POL: IT IS PLEASANT.
DO YOU SMELL THAT?
[ SNIFFS ]
I DON'T SMELL ANYTHING.
EXACTLY.
[ CHUCKLING ]