SOVAL: THE LOSS TO THE VULCAN
PEOPLE IS INCALCULABLE.
P'JEM WAS ONE OF OUR MOST
REVERED SANCTUARIES.
FORREST: AMBASSADOR,
WE ARE VERY SORRY
FOR YOUR LOSS.
BUT WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
THE HIGH COMMAND HAS TO
TAKE SOME RESPONSIBILITY.
YOU WERE USING THE MONASTERY
AS A SURVEILLANCE STATION.
WE WERE OBSERVING A DANGEROUS
AND AGGRESSIVE NEIGHBOR.
THE ANDORIANS WOULDN'T
HAVE FOUND THE STATION
IF YOUR PEOPLE HADN'T
INTERFERED.
THEY'VE BEEN IN SPACE
FOR SIX MONTHS,
AND THEY'VE ALREADY
DESTABILIZED AN ENTIRE SECTOR.
I'M AFRAID I CAN'T AGREE
WITH THAT, AMBASSADOR.
THIS WAS A VOLATILE SITUATION
LONG BEFORE STARFLEET
GOT INVOLVED.
PERHAPS IF YOU'D BEEN
A LITTLE MORE OPEN WITH US,
THIS TRAGEDY MIGHT
HAVE BEEN AVOIDED.
WE WARNED YOU SOMETHING
LIKE THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
HE'S TOO IMPULSIVE.
CAPTAIN GARDNER
WOULD HAVE MADE
A FAR MORE SUITABLE
COMMANDING OFFICER.
THE VULCAN CONSULATE DOESN'T
MAKE COMMAND ASSIGNMENTS HERE.
THERE WAS A TIME WHEN YOUR
PEOPLE SOUGHT OUR GUIDANCE.
I REGRET THAT TIME HAS PASSED.
I'VE BEEN RECALLED TO VULCAN
FOR CONSULTATION.
IN THE MEANTIME,
OUR JOINT FLEET OPERATIONS
HAVE BEEN SUSPENDED.
Yes, Admiral?
GET ME CAPTAIN ARCHER.
Aye, sir.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
I NOTICED WE CHANGED
COURSE OVERNIGHT.
I FOUND A NEW SYSTEM IN
THE VULCAN DATABASE -- CORIDAN.
THEY'RE ONLY A FEW
LIGHT-YEARS AWAY,
SO I THOUGHT
WE'D, UH, TAKE A LOOK.
INHABITED?
JUST OVER THREE BILLION
HUMANOIDS.
APPARENTLY, THE VULCANS HAVE
A MINING AGREEMENT WITH THEM.
I HAD HOSHI SEND A MESSAGE
TO THEIR CHANCELLOR,
AND SHE INVITED US
TO VISIT THEIR CAPITAL CITY.
THEN I'LL START
SHINING MY BOOTS.
I THINK I'LL JUST TAKE HOSHI...
THIS TIME.
THE CHANCELLOR ASKED ME
TO LIMIT THE NUMBER
OF PEOPLE I BRING DOWN, UNTIL
THEY GET TO KNOW US BETTER.
OH.
IT'S REALLY TOO BAD.
ACCORDING TO THE DATABASE,
THEY'VE GOT THE LARGEST
STARSHIP CONSTRUCTION YARDS
IN THE SECTOR.
THEY'RE SUPPOSED
TO HAVE SHIPS THAT CAN RUN
CIRCLES AROUND THE VULCANS.
BETTER THAN 6.5?
THEY SAY...SOME CORIDAN SHIPS
HAVE REACHED WARP 7,
BUT, NAH, THAT'S JUST A RUMOR.
WARP 7?
YOU SHOULD LEND HOSHI
YOUR CAMERA.
I'LL BE SURE SHE TAKES
LOTS OF PICTURES.
AH, YOU HAD ME GOING THERE
FOR A MINUTE!
[ LAUGHS ]
YOU'RE JUST TOO EASY A TARGET.
-SO YOU'RE TAKING ME, RIGHT?
-Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
I'm receiving a transmission
from Starfleet Command.
It's Admiral Forrest, sir.
WAS ANYONE KILLED?
THE ANDORIANS GAVE THE MONKS
THREE HOURS
BEFORE THEY STARTED
THEIR BOMBARDMENT.
FORTUNATELY,
THEY ALL GOT OUT IN TIME.
HOW ARE THE VULCANS TAKING THIS?
NOT WELL.
I CAN'T REALLY BLAME
THE ANDORIANS
FOR REACTING THIS WAY --
JON...
IF THE ROLES WERE REVERSED,
THE VULCANS MIGHT HAVE
DONE THE SAME THING.
THE VULCANS
MAY HAVE GOOD REASON
FOR KEEPING AN EYE ON THEM;
I'VE SEEN THE REPORTS.
THESE ANDORIAN COMMANDOS
ARE A DANGEROUS GROUP.
THAT'S THE SAME CRAP THE VULCANS
USED TO SAY ABOUT US!
JON, YOU'RE DOING
A LOT OF GOOD WORK,
BUT YOU'VE GOT
TO BE MORE CAREFUL.
EARTH CAN'T BE GETTING INVOLVED
IN INTERSPECIES CONFLICTS.
I UNDERSTAND.
I'M AFRAID I'VE GOT
SOME MORE BAD NEWS.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
HAVE A SEAT.
I JUST SPOKE
WITH ADMIRAL FORREST.
[ SIGHS ]
THERE'S NO EASY WAY TO SAY THIS.
THE ANDORIANS DESTROYED
THE SANCTUARY AT P'JEM.
WERE THERE ANY SURVIVORS?
FORTUNATELY, THE MONKS...
AND THE INTELLIGENCE
OPERATIVES
WERE GIVEN ADVANCE WARNING.
THEY'RE FINE.
WAS THERE TIME TO REMOVE
ANY OF THE RELICS?
ARCHER: I DON'T KNOW.
THE HIGH COMMAND BELIEVES
WE'RE TO BLAME FOR THIS.
THEY'RE...
SENDING A SHIP
TO TAKE YOU BACK TO VULCAN.
IT'LL BE HERE IN TWO DAYS.
I WON'T HAVE TIME TO COMPLETE
MY SCANS OF THIS SECTOR.
I'LL ASK ENSIGN MAYWEATHER
TO FINISH THEM.
MAYBE I WASN'T CLEAR.
THIS ISN'T A TEMPORARY TRANSFER.
THEY'RE REASSIGNING YOU.
I UNDERSTAND
THE SITUATION, CAPTAIN.
I'M CERTAIN THE HIGH COMMAND
WILL FIND YOU
A SUITABLE REPLACEMENT.
AM I THE ONLY ONE WHO HAS
A PROBLEM WITH THIS?
BECAUSE YOU SEEM
PERFECTLY FINE.
MY ASSIGNMENT
TO THE ENTERPRISE WAS
ONLY SUPPOSED
TO LAST EIGHT DAYS.
IT WAS UNREALISTIC TO EXPECT IT
TO CONTINUE INDEFINITELY.
THE HIGH COMMAND IS
LOOKING FOR A SCAPEGOAT,
SOMEONE TO BLAME.
THEY CAN'T PUNISH ME,
SO THEY'RE TAKING IT OUT
ON MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
SOUNDS LIKE AN EMOTIONAL
REACTION, IF YOU ASK ME.
I AM LARGELY RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED.
DON'T GIVE YOURSELF
TOO MUCH CREDIT.
I WAS THE ONE WHO FOUND
P'JEM IN THE DATABASE,
AND I LED THE LANDING PARTY.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW I'M FILING
A PROTEST WITH THE HIGH COMMAND.
THAT WON'T MAKE ANY DIFFERENCE.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
CAPTAIN, I WAS ASSIGNED
TO ENTERPRISE NOT SIMPLY
AS AN OBSERVER,
BUT TO REPRESENT THE INTERESTS
OF THE VULCAN PEOPLE.
IT'S CLEAR IN THE EYES
OF MY SUPERIORS
I HAVEN'T DONE THAT.
THEY HAVE NO RIGHT
TO DO THIS TO YOU.
YOU'RE A PART OF MY CREW.
FOR ANOTHER 48 HOURS.
WAS THERE ANYTHING ELSE?
NO.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
TUCKER: THIS IS JUST ANOTHER
PART OF THE JOKE, RIGHT?
ARCHER: SORRY, TRIP. I'VE GOT
TO TAKE T'POL ON THIS ONE.
I NEED TO SPEND SOME TIME
WITH HER ALONE.
TUCKER: NOW I KNOW YOU'RE
PULLING MY LEG.
T'POL IS BEING TRANSFERRED.
A VULCAN SHIP'S ON ITS WAY
TO TAKE HER BACK.
WHAT?
MEET ME FOR LUNCH.
I'LL FILL YOU IN.
[ OVERLAPPING CHATTER ]
MAY I?
AH.
I JUST HEARD
ABOUT YOUR TRANSFER.
I'M SORRY YOU'LL
BE LEAVING US.
I'M SURE YOU'LL EXCEL
AT WHATEVER NEW ASSIGNMENT
YOU'RE GIVEN.
I HAVEN'T RECEIVED
ANOTHER ASSIGNMENT.
I ASSUMED YOU WERE
BEING PROMOTED.
MY SUPERIORS BELIEVE
THAT I AM RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE P'JEM SANCTUARY.
DO YOU AGREE WITH
THEIR ASSESSMENT?
IT'S THE LOGICAL CONCLUSION.
I'M CERTAIN THE HIGH COMMAND
WOULD RECONSIDER YOUR TRANSFER
IF THEY KNEW EVERYTHING
YOU'VE DONE FOR THIS CREW.
YOU REALIZE YOU'RE NOT
THE FIRST VULCAN OFFICER
TO BE POSTED
ABOARD A HUMAN STARSHIP.
THE HIGH COMMAND
HAS TRIED THIS BEFORE,
BUT NONE OF THE OTHERS
LASTED MORE THAN A FEW WEEKS.
THEY FOUND THEIR CREWMATES TOO
CHAOTIC AND UNPREDICTABLE. HEH!
BUT YOU'VE BEEN HERE
MORE THAN SIX MONTHS,
AND YOU HAVEN'T MERELY
TOLERATED THIS CREW,
YOU'VE BECOME PART OF IT.
ISN'T IT LOGICAL TO TAKE PRIDE
IN THAT ACCOMPLISHMENT?
"PRIDE" IS A HUMAN INDULGENCE.
I SUPPOSE IT IS.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
OH, I HAVE IT ON GOOD AUTHORITY
THAT SEVERAL CREW MEMBERS
ARE PLANNING A GATHERING
IN YOUR HONOR.
I BELIEVE IT'S CALLED
A "GOING-AWAY PARTY."
I'D KEEP ON ALERT
IF I WERE YOU.
SO...
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT CORIDAN?
THERE ARE THREE BILLION
INHABITANTS,
MOSTLY CONCENTRATED
IN SEVERAL CITIES
IN THE EQUATORIAL REGION.
I WASN'T ASKING
FOR THE STATISTICS.
YOUR PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
COMING HERE FOR DECADES.
YOU MUST KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT THEIR CULTURE...
KINDS OF FOOD THEY EAT,
WHAT THEY DO FOR FUN.
THE VULCAN DATABASE DOESN'T
CONTAIN THAT INFORMATION.
'COURSE NOT.
I AM UNCERTAIN WHY I WAS
CHOSEN FOR THIS MISSION.
THESE PEOPLE HAVE
NEVER SEEN HUMANS BEFORE.
IT MAKES SENSE FOR SOMEONE
WITH A FAMILIAR FACE
TO MAKE THE INTRODUCTIONS.
I HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO COMPLETE
BEFORE THE VULCAN SHIP ARRIVES.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL GET YOU BACK
IN PLENTY OF TIME.
I JUST...
THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
ENJOY ONE FINAL MISSION
WITH YOUR CAPTAIN.
OR MAYBE I SHOULD JUST TAKE YOU
BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
WE'RE ONLY A FEW MINUTES
FROM THE CAPITAL.
RETURNING TO THE SHIP NOW
WOULD BE A WASTE OF FUEL.
Enterprise to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD, TRIP.
We're reading a ship
closing on you fast.
I GOT IT.
SOME KIND OF
FIXED-WING AIRCRAFT.
DID THE CHANCELLOR SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT SENDING AN ESCORT?
[ IMPACT ]
I DON'T THINK THEY'RE AN ESCORT.
Alien vessel, reduce
to one-quarter power
and adjust heading
to 317 mark 5.
I'M TAKING EVASIVE ACTION.
BRING THE PLASMA WEAPONS
ON LINE.
READY.
FIRE.
[ THUNDER ]
[ WATER DRIPPING ]
ARCHER: HOUDINI COULD
GET OUT OF THIS.
T'POL: PERHAPS YOU SHOULD INVITE
HIM ON YOUR NEXT MISSION.
ARCHER: HARRY HOUDINI
WAS A MAGICIAN,
AN ESCAPE ARTIST.
HE WAS FAMOUS FOR BEING
ABLE TO FREE HIMSELF
FROM ANY KIND OF RESTRAINT --
ROPE, CHAINS, ANYTHING.
T'POL: THAT SEEMS UNLIKELY.
ARCHER: THAT'S WHY
HE WAS CALLED A MAGICIAN.
SOME PEOPLE SAY
HE WAS DOUBLE-JOINTED.
I DON'T SUPPOSE VULCANS
ARE DOUBLE-JOINTED.
T'POL: UNFORTUNATELY NOT.
A VULCAN.
WHAT BRINGS YOU TO CORIDAN?
IF YOU WANT ANSWERS,
TALK TO ME.
YOU'RE HER SUPERIOR?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I DON'T RECOGNIZE YOUR SPECIES.
I'M HUMAN.
FROM THE PLANET EARTH.
NEVER HEARD OF VULCANS
TAKING ORDERS FROM ANYONE.
THERE'S BEEN
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
ARCHER: WE'RE HERE AT THE
INVITATION OF YOUR CHANCELLOR.
SHE'S NOT MY CHANCELLOR.
THAT GOVERNMENT IS KEPT
IN POWER BY THE VULCANS.
MAN: IF YOU'RE WITH THEM,
YOU'RE ON THE WRONG SIDE.
WHAT KIND OF WEAPON IS THIS?
IF YOU WON'T TELL ME...
IT'S A PHASE-PISTOL.
WE'LL PUT THESE TO GOOD USE.
I'M CURIOUS ABOUT YOUR STARSHIP.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME
ABOUT IT?
OUR PROTEIN RESEQUENCER CAN MAKE
CHICKEN SANDWICHES.
T'POL: STOP! HE'S NOT
A TACTICAL OFFICER.
HE'S THE SHIP'S STEWARD.
[ ARCHER GROANS ]
T'POL: WE'RE HERE
TO PREPARE A BANQUET
FOR YOUR CHANCELLOR.
YOUR PEOPLE HAVE A REPUTATION
FOR TRUTHFULNESS.
YOU WOULDN'T BE LYING TO ME,
WOULD YOU, VULCAN?
OH, NOW I UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN, AREN'T YOU?
PERHAPS.
WHOEVER YOU ARE,
YOU PICKED THE WRONG TIME
FOR A VISIT.
A STEWARD?
WE BELIEVE YOUR SHUTTLE
WAS FORCED DOWN
BY MEMBERS
OF A RADICAL FACTION.
BUT SINCE THE ATTACK TOOK PLACE
OUTSIDE OUR SENSOR GRID,
YOUR OFFICERS WON'T BE
EASY TO FIND.
YOU DIDN'T TELL US
ABOUT ANY FACTIONS.
THEY'RE A SMALL GROUP.
WE HAD NO IDEA
THEY WERE CAPABLE
OF AN ATTACK LIKE THIS,
BUT BE ASSURED, COMMANDER,
YOUR PEOPLE ARE ALMOST
CERTAINLY STILL ALIVE.
ALMOST CERTAINLY?
THE RADICALS
WILL WANT SOMETHING
IN EXCHANGE FOR THE HOSTAGES;
THEY ALWAYS DO.
SIDE ARMS, DICOBALT EXPLOSIVES.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT YOU
DON'T GIVE THEM ANYTHING.
IS THIS HOW YOU PROTECT
YOUR VISITORS?
YOU MIGHT HAVE TOLD US
ABOUT YOUR LITTLE WAR
BEFORE YOU INVITED US DOWN.
WE'RE NOT AT WAR, COMMANDER.
THIS IS AN ISOLATED INCIDENT.
I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU CALL IT.
WE JUST WANT TO KNOW
WHERE ARE PEOPLE ARE.
WE ARE DOING EVERYTHING
IN OUR POWER TO FIND THEM.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO SIT
ON OUR HANDS AND WAIT
FOR A RANSOM NOTE.
START SCANNING FOR HUMAN
AND VULCAN BIO-SIGNS.
HOSHI: THERE ARE BILLIONS
OF PEOPLE DOWN THERE.
IT COULD TAKE DAYS.
IT MIGHT BE EASIER
TO LOCATE THE SHUTTLEPOD.
I'LL TRY, BUT IF THE POD'S
BEEN POWERED DOWN,
IT'S ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE
TO PICK UP ITS SIGNATURE.
WE'VE GOT TO START SOMEWHERE.
READY?
YES.
GO.
[ GRUNTS ]
EASY.
[ BOTH GROAN ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
COME ON.
GO.
[ GRUNTING ]
OH!
[ GRUNTS ]
I THINK WE GOT
A LITTLE HIGHER THAT TIME.
ONLY A FEW CENTIMETERS.
THAT'S NOT FRUSTRATION
I HEAR IN YOUR VOICE?
NO.
GOOD.
LET'S TRY IT AGAIN.
ONE, TWO, THREE!
READY?
YES.
GO.
I THINK THESE ARE STARTING
TO COME LOOSE.
HOW ABOUT YOURS?
SLIGHTLY.
IF WE CAN TURN AROUND,
FACE EACH OTHER...
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO UNTIE THESE KNOTS.
YOU'D THINK
THAT VULCAN DATABASE
MIGHT HAVE MENTIONED
THESE PEOPLE WERE
FIGHTING A CIVIL WAR.
T'POL: THE DATABASE
IS ACCURATE.
THE CORIDAN GOVERNMENT
DOESN'T VIEW THIS
AS A CIVIL WAR.
ARCHER: I IMAGINE YOUR PEOPLE
ARE GOING TO WANT
THEIR DATABASE BACK, TOO.
WELL, THEY CAN HAVE IT.
[ BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY ]
CAN YOU REACH THE KNOT?
I BELIEVE SO.
WITHOUT THE DATABASE,
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE
FOUND THIS PLANET...
OR P'JEM.
YOU'RE NOT RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE ANY IDEA
THAT YOUR PEOPLE
HAD INSTALLED
A LISTENING POST.
[ GRUNTS ]
OR THAT THERE WERE
ANDORIAN COMMANDOS THERE.
ENTERPRISE HAD NO GOOD REASON
TO VISIT A VULCAN SANCTUARY.
I HAD THE OPPORTUNITY
TO PROTEST,
BUT I CHOSE NOT TO.
IT'S CLEAR THAT LIVING
AMONG HUMANS
HAS CAUSED MY REASONING
TO BECOME COMPROMISED.
ARCHER: I THINK I UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE RUNNING AWAY
BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID
TO BECOME ONE OF US.
I AM NOT RUNNING AWAY.
THEN WHY AREN'T YOU
FIGHTING THIS TRANSFER?
ARCHER: YOUR PEOPLE TOOK
SOMETHING AWAY
FROM MY FATHER
THAT MEANT A LOT TO HIM.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO DO
THE SAME THING TO ME.
OH.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
GET HIS WEAPON.
STOP!
IT'S DEFINITELY
A DITANIUM SIGNATURE.
ABOUT FOUR KILOMETERS
OUTSIDE THE CAPITAL.
IT'S PRACTICALLY
UNDER THEIR NOSES.
FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL,
THE ENTIRE CAPITAL
IS SURROUNDED BY A SHANTYTOWN.
THERE ARE ALMOST
AS MANY BIO-SIGNS
ON THE OUTSKIRTS AS THERE
ARE INSIDE THE CITY.
LOOKS LIKE THESE PEOPLE
HAVE A LOT TO LEARN
ABOUT BUILDING A FREE SOCIETY.
HAVE YOU FOUND HUMAN
OR VULCAN BIO-SIGNS?
NOT YET.
WHAT ABOUT THE POD'S
TRANSPONDER?
THEY MUST HAVE
SWITCHED IT OFF.
SIR, I'VE GOT A RESCUE TEAM
STANDING BY
IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
HOLD ON, MALCOLM.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF THIS IS OUR POD.
I DON'T WANT
TO GO DOWN AND FIND
IT'S SOME ALIEN TRACTOR.
IT'S OUR SHUTTLEPOD.
I'M CERTAIN OF IT.
ALL I'M SUGGESTING IS
WE GO DOWN
AND HAVE A LOOK AROUND.
[ BEEPING ]
SIR, WE'RE BEING HAILED.
AUDIO ONLY.
-WHO IS IT?
-I CAN'T TELL.
PUT THEM THROUGH.
Is this Enterprise?
YES. AND YOU ARE?
We're holding your captain
and your steward.
In exchange
for their safe return,
we want 40
of your phase weapons,
the same type we found
aboard your shuttle.
You'll be hailed
at this time tomorrow.
WAIT. LET ME TALK
TO THE CAPTAIN.
I'm sure you wouldn't want
any harm to come to her.
We'll rely on your
full compliance.
HELLO?
HOSHI: THEY'VE CUT TRANSMISSION.
WERE YOU ABLE TO TRACE IT?
THEY WERE USING
A TRIAXILATING SIGNAL.
THEY CALLED THE CAPTAIN "HER."
ARE WE SURE THEY'VE GOT
THE RIGHT HOSTAGES?
AT LEAST IT SOUNDS
LIKE THEY'RE STILL ALIVE.
REED: FOR HOW LONG?
WE DON'T HAVE 40 PHASE-PISTOLS.
WE'VE GOT 15.
AND EVEN IF WE GIVE THEM
TO THESE PEOPLE,
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE
THEY'LL KEEP THEIR WORD.
WE KNOW WHERE THE SHUTTLE IS.
WE HAVE TO SEND
A TEAM DOWN NOW,
WHILE WE STILL HAVE
THE ELEMENT OF SURPRISE.
[ CONSOLE BEEPING ]
WE'RE GETTING
ANOTHER TRANSMISSION.
PROBABLY THOUGHT OF
SOMETHING ELSE THEY WANT.
HOSHI: IT'S NOT FROM
THE PLANET.
IT'S COMING FROM A VULCAN SHIP,
THE NI'VAR.
PUT IT UP.
WHERE'S CAPTAIN ARCHER?
HE'S NOT HERE RIGHT NOW.
CAN I HELP YOU?
INFORM HIM THAT WE'LL BE
ARRIVING WITHIN THE HOUR.
YOU GUYS MADE GREAT TIME.
WE WEREN'T EXPECTING YOU
UNTIL TOMORROW.
YOU OBVIOUSLY MADE AN ERROR
IN YOUR CALCULATIONS.
PLEASE HAVE SUBCOMMANDER T'POL
READY TO DEPART WHEN WE ARRIVE.
WE'VE GOT A...
BIT OF A PROBLEM.
SHE'S NOT HERE, EITHER.
SHE AND THE CAPTAIN WERE ON
THEIR WAY TO THE CAPITAL CITY
WHEN THEY WERE KIDNAPPED.
HOW CONVENIENT.
I'M TELLING YOU,
THEY WERE KIDNAPPED.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THIS?
MAYBE THE RANSOM DEMAND
WE JUST RECEIVED
GAVE US A CLUE.
THEY THREATENED
TO KILL THEM BOTH
IF WE DIDN'T GIVE THEM
WHAT THEY WANT.
IT WOULD BE IRRATIONAL
TO KILL THE HOSTAGES.
THEY WOULD LOSE
THEIR NEGOTIATING POSITION.
MAYBE WE'RE NOT DEALING
WITH THE MOST RATIONAL PEOPLE
DOWN THERE.
DID YOU CONSIDER THAT?
SINCE THIS SITUATION INVOLVES
A VULCAN OFFICER,
WE WILL TAKE OVER
THE INVESTIGATION.
IT WOULD BE BEST
IF YOU REFRAINED
FROM ANY FOOLISH ENDEAVORS.
WHAT THE HELL'S
THAT SUPPOSED --
I'M GETTING REAL SICK
OF BEING CUT OFF.
YOUR VESSEL IS ILL-EQUIPPED
TO MOUNT A RESCUE MISSION.
YOU WOULD MOST LIKELY
BECOME CAPTIVES YOURSELVES.
MY TEAM WILL PENETRATE
THEIR BASE OF OPERATIONS.
-WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
-SOUNDS TO ME
LIKE YOU'RE PLANNING AN ASSAULT.
TUCKER: DID IT EVER OCCUR
TO YOU THAT THAT COULD
GET THE CAPTAIN
AND T'POL KILLED?
WE'VE DEALT WITH THIS SORT
OF THREAT IN THE PAST.
SWIFT, DECISIVE ACTION
IS THE LOGICAL RESPONSE.
YOU'RE AWFULLY
TRIGGER-HAPPY FOR SOMEONE
WHO'S REPRESSED HIS EMOTIONS.
THEY'VE THREATENED THE LIFE
OF A VULCAN OFFICER.
WE MUST DISCOURAGE
ANY SUCH INCIDENTS
IN THE FUTURE.
REED: THIS ISN'T YOUR PLANET.
MAYBE THE CORIDAN GOVERNMENT HAS
SOMETHING TO SAY ABOUT THIS.
SOPEK: I'VE ALREADY BEEN
IN CONTACT WITH THE CHANCELLOR.
SHE'S GIVEN ME FULL AUTHORITY
TO IMPLEMENT THIS ACTION.
YOU DON'T REALLY CARE
WHAT HAPPENS TO THEM, DO YOU?
TUCKER: YOU PROBABLY
WOULDN'T MIND IF
THEY GOT CAUGHT
IN THE CROSSFIRE.
YOU'D CONSIDER IT PAYBACK
FOR WHAT HAPPENED AT P'JEM.
IT'S NOT VULCAN POLICY
TO NEGOTIATE WITH TERRORISTS.
NOT EVEN IF IT SAVES LIVES?
ANY DATA YOU MAY HAVE
ON THE LOCATION OF YOUR CAPTAIN
AND THE SUBCOMMANDER
WOULD BE USEFUL.
SORRY.
WE DON'T HAVE ANYTHING.
WARM UP THE SHUTTLEPOD.
[ GRUNTING ]
WE CAN'T EAT LIKE THIS.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
FRIENDLY.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
CAN YOU PICK UP YOURS?
NO.
[ SIGHS ]
DIG IN, SUBCOMMANDER.
I DON'T THINK YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO SEND THIS BACK
FOR SOME PLOMEEK BROTH.
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
ARCHER: I DIDN'T ASK
IF YOU WERE HUNGRY.
YOU NEED TO KEEP UP
YOUR STRENGTH.
[ GRUNTS ]
SO EAT.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ SLURPING ]
ARCHER: LOOK AT THIS.
[ CONSOLE BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
IT'S THE VULCANS.
HERE WE GO.
THIS IS SOPEK.
WHERE IS COMMANDER TUCKER?
HE'S UNAVAILABLE AT THE MOMENT.
CAN I TAKE A MESSAGE?
I WANT TO KNOW WHERE
THAT SHUTTLEPOD WAS GOING.
WHAT SHUTTLEPOD IS THAT?
THE ONE THAT LEFT YOUR
LAUNCH BAY NINE MINUTES AGO.
I REALLY WOULDN'T KNOW, SIR.
WE GET SHUTTLEPODS COMING
AND GOING ALL THE TIME.
IT'S A LITTLE LIKE UNION STATION
AROUND HERE.
I WANT TO KNOW WHERE
COMMANDER TUCKER IS.
I'M SORRY.
YOUR TRANSMISSION'S BREAKING UP.
TUCKER: I GUESS NOT EVERYONE
GETS TO LIVE IN EMERALD CITY.
REED: YEAH.
[ GRUNTING ]
SHRAN: YOU SHOULD HAVE
LISTENED TO THE VULCAN.
HE WARNED YOU AGAINST DOING
ANYTHING FOOLISH.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
LOOKING OUT FOR YOU PINKSKINS.
IF YOU HAD GONE ANYWHERE
NEAR THAT SHUTTLEPOD,
YOU'D HAVE BEEN KILLED.
THEY LEFT IT IN THE OPEN
FOR YOU TO FIND.
HOW DO YOU KNOW WHAT
SOPEK TOLD ME?
THAT WAS A SECURE TRANSMISSION.
SOPEK IS THE SENIOR VULCAN
OFFICER IN THE SECTOR.
NATURALLY, WE KEEP HIM
UNDER CLOSE SURVEILLANCE.
WE'VE BEEN MONITORING
ALL VULCAN TRANSMISSIONS
AND SHIP DEPLOYMENTS
SINCE THE INCIDENT AT P'JEM.
WE KNOW THEY'RE PREPARING
FOR A WAR AGAINST US.
I'M NO FAN OF THE VULCANS,
BUT THEY'RE NOT WARMONGERS.
THERE'S ALREADY A WAR GOING ON,
AND THE VULCANS
ARE IN THE MIDDLE OF IT.
SEVERAL REBEL FACTIONS HERE
ARE WORKING TO OVERTHROW
THEIR GOVERNMENT --
A CORRUPT GOVERNMENT
THAT HAS VERY CLOSE TIES
TO YOUR PEACE-LOVING,
LOGICAL FRIENDS.
SO, YOU AND THE REBELS FIGURE
YOU BOTH HAVE A COMMON ENEMY.
THE HOSTAGE-TAKERS
HAVE NO PLANS TO RETURN
YOUR CAPTAIN OR THE FEMALE.
ONCE YOU DELIVER THE WEAPONS,
THEY'LL BE KILLED.
FORTUNATELY FOR YOU,
WE HAVE A RELATIONSHIP
WITH THE DOWNTRODDEN HERE.
YOU TRIED TO KILL US
LAST TIME WE MET.
WHY ARE YOU TRYING
TO HELP US NOW?
I HAVEN'T...SLEPT WELL
SINCE OUR ENCOUNTER AT
THE VULCAN SANCTUARY.
I DON'T LIKE BEING
INDEBTED TO ANYONE,
LEAST OF ALL YOUR CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU NEVER WOULD HAVE FOUND
THAT SPY STATION
WITHOUT HIS HELP.
ONCE HE'S FREE,
MY DEBT WILL BE REPAID
IN FULL.
SHOW THEM.
YOUR PEOPLE ARE
BEING HELD HERE.
THESE ARE BARRACKS
FOR THE GUARDS.
-HOW MANY?
-AT LEAST FOUR
INSIDE THE COMPOUND,
TWO MORE UP ON THE WALL,
HERE, AND TWO GUARDS
OUTSIDE THE GATE,
ALL ARMED WITH PARTICLE WEAPONS.
HOW'D YOU GET
THIS LEVEL OF DETAIL?
WE HAVE AN OPERATIVE
INSIDE THE COMPOUND.
UNLESS HE'S GOING
TO TAKE OUT THESE GUARDS,
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
AN EASY TIME GETTING
ALL THE WAY TO THE HOSTAGES.
SHRAN: IT'S NOT YOUR CONCERN.
TUCKER: IT IS IF
YOU GET THE CAPTAIN KILLED.
YOU'RE OUTNUMBERED
FOUR TO ONE.
WOULDN'T YOU LIKE
TO IMPROVE THOSE ODDS?
THEY COULD BE USEFUL.
GIVE THEM THEIR WEAPONS.
[ BEEPING ]
Captain, can you hear me?
TRIP?
It's me and Malcolm, sir.
We're about
half a kilometer away.
JUST THE TWO OF YOU?
Not exactly; we met up
with some old friends
down here -- Andorians.
Apparently, one of them thinks
he owes you a favor.
HE COULDN'T HAVE PICKED
A BETTER TIME.
One of the people guarding you
is working with them.
When he unties you,
head for the gate.
It's about 20 meters
from the building you're in.
Until he shows up,
just sit tight.
THAT WON'T BE A PROBLEM.
AH.
COLD, ISN'T IT?
ANDORIAN ALE?
IT'LL WARM YOU UP.
[ RUSTLING ]
WHO'S THAT?
TUCKER: AH, IT'S JUST
MY FRIEND. NOTHING TO --
[ GRUNTING ]
GET OFF ME! HEY.
LET ME GO. OH.
[ BOTTLE SHATTERS ]
OH!
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?!
[ GRUNTS ]
GET DOWN.
VULCANS! DID YOU KNOW
THEY WERE PLANNING TO DO THIS?
YOU'RE THE ONES WHO HAVE
THEIR COM SYSTEM BUGGED.
OUR ESCAPE PLAN'S SHOT TO HELL.
[ EXPLOSION ]
TUCKER: WE'VE GOT
TO GET THEM OUT OF THERE.
TUCKER: GOOD TO SEE YOU,
CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WHAT'S GOING ON?
TUCKER: THE VULCANS CRASHED
OUR RESCUE PARTY.
THANKS.
I BELIEVE THIS IS YOURS.
IT'S THE SCANNER SHE GAVE ME
FROM THE VULCAN LISTENING POST.
SEEMS YOU WENT TO A LOT
OF TROUBLE TO RETURN IT.
I'M HERE FOR ONLY ONE REASON.
I NEED A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
MY DEBT IS REPAID.
YOUR PRESENCE HERE IS
A VIOLATION
OF THE TAU CETI ACCORDS.
YOU LECTURE US
ABOUT TREATY VIOLATIONS?
SOPEK: PUT DOWN YOUR WEAPONS!
SHRAN: I KNOW BETTER THAN TO
LOWER MY GUARD AROUND VULCANS!
ARCHER: LOOK, WE'RE ALL
ON THE SAME SIDE HERE.
[ T'POL GROANS ]
LET'S GET HER TO THE SHIP.
SHE'S NO LONGER
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY.
WE'LL TREAT HER ON THE NI'VAR.
SHE'S STILL MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
IS THE POD CLOSE?
-YES, SIR.
-LET'S GO.
YOU SHOULD BE THE ONE
DYING, NOT HER.
HOW IS SHE?
HER INJURIES
WERE QUITE EXTENSIVE.
WILL SHE LIVE?
I WISH I COULD SAY.
I KNOW HOW YOU MUST FEEL.
SHE SAVED MY LIFE ONCE, TOO.
SHE CAN BE A REAL...
PAIN IN THE ASS.
STUBBORN...ARROGANT.
SOMETIMES SHE MAKES ME
ANGRY ENOUGH,
I WANT TO SHOVE HER
OUT AN AIRLOCK.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY
THE HIGH COMMAND'S UPSET.
BUT IT TOOK A LOT OF COURAGE
TO STEP IN FRONT OF
THAT PLASMA BULLET.
DO YOU REALLY WANT TO TAKE HER
BACK HOME IN DISGRACE?
NOTHING CAN EXCUSE
WHAT SHE DID AT THE SANCTUARY.
ARCHER: I'M NOT ASKING ANYONE
TO PIN A MEDAL ON HER.
ALL I'M ASKING IS THAT SHE BE
GIVEN A SECOND CHANCE.
IF A RESPECTED VULCAN CAPTAIN
WENT BEFORE THE HIGH COMMAND
AND MADE A PLEA
ON T'POL'S BEHALF, TOLD THEM
HOW SHE SAVED THE LIFE
OF A SUPERIOR OFFICER,
WOULDN'T THEY THINK TWICE
ABOUT THIS TRANSFER?
I CAN'T RETURN WITHOUT HER.
SHE SUFFERED EXTREME TRAUMA.
I WOULDN'T ADVISE MOVING HER
FOR QUITE SOME TIME.
I'M MEETING WITH
THE HIGH COMMAND IN THREE DAYS.
PERHAPS, IF THERE'S TIME,
I'LL DISCUSS THIS MATTER
WITH THEM.
THANK YOU.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHOA, WHOA.
YOU WERE SHOT.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER?
CAPTAIN SOPEK?
HE'S ALL RIGHT, THANKS TO YOU.
I'D LIKE TO RETURN
TO MY QUAR--
I'M AFRAID YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO STAY HERE,
AT LEAST ANOTHER, UH, 24 HOURS.
YOU MADE QUITE
AN IMPRESSION ON SOPEK.
I'VE GOT A FEELING
HE'S GOING TO TALK
TO THE HIGH COMMAND
ABOUT THAT TRANSFER ORDER.
I'D SAY THE ODDS ARE PRETTY GOOD
YOU'RE GOING TO BE WITH US
FOR A WHILE LONGER.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
CONSULTED ME FIRST.
[ SIGHS ]
IT'S PROBABLY NOT TOO LATE
IF YOU WANT TO CATCH UP TO HIM.
THAT WON'T BE POSSIBLE.
LEAVING SICK BAY WOULD VIOLATE
MY DOCTOR'S ORDERS.