THE CAPTAIN SAID THEY'D BE
MAPPING THIS ASTEROID FIELD,
BUT I CAN'T SEE
HEAD NOR TAILS OF THEM.
MAYBE IT'S
ANOTHER ASTEROID FIELD.
REED: NO, THIS IS THE ONE.
TWO PRIMARIES.
17 PLANETESIMALS.
WELL, THEY WEREN'T EXPECTING US
BACK FOR THREE DAYS.
MAYBE THEY FINISHED AND WENT OFF
TO DO SOMETHING ELSE.
WELL, WITH
OUR SENSOR ARRAY DOWN,
WE WON'T KNOW WHEN THEY GET BACK
UNTIL WE SEE THEM.
ANY LUCK WITH THE COM?
DEAD AS A DOORNAIL.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
WELL, NO DOUBT
YOU'LL HAVE YOUR BOYS
TAKE THIS POD APART
PIECE BY PIECE
ONCE IT'S BACK
IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
WELL, I'D FEEL A LOT
MORE COMFORTABLE
HAVING EVERYTHING
IN WORKING ORDER
BY THE TIME ENTERPRISE
GETS BACK.
REED: OH. WELL,
TINKER ALL YOU LIKE.
I'VE GOT A COPY
OF "ULYSSES" HERE.
I DOUBT I'LL EVEN BE
HALFWAY THROUGH IT
BY THE TIME THE SHIP GETS BACK.
I'D RATHER REALIGN EVERY
MICROCIRCUIT ON THIS SHUTTLE
THAN TRY TO WADE
THROUGH THAT BABY.
BRITISH SCHOOLS
HAVE A CORE CURRICULUM.
IT SERVES TO PROVIDE
A WELL-ROUNDED EDUCATION.
SOMETIMES I THINK
YOU NORTH AMERICANS
READ NOTHING BUT COMIC BOOKS
AND THOSE RIDICULOUS
SCIENCE-FICTION NOVELS.
I'LL HAVE YOU KNOW THAT SUPERMAN
WAS LACED WITH METAPHOR.
[ REED CHUCKLES ]
SUBTEXT LAYERED ON SUBTEXT.
OH, IF ONLY DR. COCHRANE
HAD BEEN A EUROPEAN,
THE VULCANS WOULD HAVE BEEN
FAR LESS RETICENT TO HELP US.
BUT NO.
HE HAD TO BE FROM MONTANA.
[ CHUCKLES ]
PROBABLY SPENT
HIS NIGHTS READING
ABOUT COWBOYS AND INDIANS.
TUCKER: WELL, I DON'T
RECALL ANY EUROPEANS
FIGURING OUT HOW TO BUILD
A WARP ENGINE.
COMMANDER.
NO BRITS, NO ITALIANS,
NO SERBO-CROATIANS.
REED: COMMANDER.
I THINK YOU'D BETTER COME
AND TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
TUCKER: BRING US IN CLOSER.
IS IT A SHIP?
IF THE DAMN SENSORS WERE
ONLY WORKING, WE COULD...
BRING US AROUND AGAIN.
THERE. SLOW DOWN.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
HOW ARE THE TESNIANS DOING?
DR. PHLOX CAN ONLY KEEP
12 OF THEM
IN THE DECON CHAMBER AT A TIME.
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHER --
WHAT IS IT -- 22?
HOSHI: HE'S ROTATING THEM.
THEY SEEM TO BE DOING FINE
ON OUR ATMOSPHERE,
BUT THEY NEED AT LEAST SIX HOURS
OF BORON GAS A DAY.
HE SAYS WE'VE GOT ENOUGH
TO GET THEM HOME.
HAVE YOU LEARNED
THEIR LANGUAGE?
HOSHI: YES, SIR.
WHAT DO THEY HAVE TO SAY?
THEY'RE PRETTY RATTLED.
MOST OF THEM HAD BEEN
ON THAT SHIP FOR YEARS.
IT'S A LOT TO DIGEST.
THEY LOST EVERYTHING.
THEY'RE ALIVE.
DOES THE CAPTAIN HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT HAPPENED?
HOSHI: NO. AND HE FEELS TERRIBLE
ABOUT THE DAMAGE TO ENTERPRISE.
HE HAS NO IDEA WHAT WENT WRONG.
WHEN THEY APPROACHED
OUR DOCKING PORT,
THEY LOST CONTROL OF THEIR
SENSOR ARRAY, AND THEN
A FEW SECONDS LATER, THEIR
NAVIGATION SYSTEM WENT OUT.
THANK GOD THEIR ESCAPE PODS
WERE WORKING.
I SAW THE WRECKAGE
ON THE ASTEROID.
THERE WASN'T MUCH LEFT.
ARCHER TO MAYWEATHER.
WHAT'S OUR E.T.A.?
We should reach Tesnia
in about 20 hours, sir.
GOOD WORK.
THAT SHOULD GET US BACK
TO OUR RENDEZVOUS COORDINATES
WELL BEFORE
TRIP AND MALCOLM GET THERE.
LET'S DROP OUT OF WARP
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
I WANT TO INSPECT THE DAMAGE
TO THE LAUNCH DOORS.
Aye, sir.
WHO'S IN CHARGE OF ENGINEERING
WHILE TRIP'S AWAY?
LIEUTENANT HESS.
TELL HER TO GET
A TEAM WORKING
ON A NEW STARBOARD DOOR
FOR LAUNCH BAY TWO.
EVERYTHING ELSE
CHECK OUT ALL RIGHT?
ASTROMETRICS DETECTED WHAT
COULD BE MICRO-SINGULARITIES
IN THE VICINITY OF
THE ASTEROID FIELD.
MICRO-SINGULARITIES
ARE A VULCAN MYTH.
THERE'S NO SCIENTIFIC EVIDENCE
THAT THEY EXIST.
OUR DEFLECTORS REGISTERED
SOME UNUSUAL CHARGED PARTICLES
AT THE SAME TIME THE TESNIAN
SHIP BEGAN TO MALFUNCTION.
ANY SIMILAR DAMAGE
ON ENTERPRISE?
NO, BUT OUR HULL PLATING
WAS POLARIZED.
MM-HMM.
MICRO-SINGULARITIES.
IF THE VULCANS HAD THEIR WAY,
THEY'D BLAME THEM
FOR THE COMMON COLD.
HOW ABOUT THE LIFEBOATS?
THEY COULD HAVE LAUNCHED
THE LIFEBOATS BEFORE THE CRASH.
REED: THEY'D BE HERE.
THEY ONLY GO 300 KPH.
THEY'D BE RIGHT HERE,
WAITING FOR US TO RETURN.
ARE WE SURE
THERE ARE NO SURVIVORS?
COMMANDER, WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO.
WE CAN'T JUST LEAVE.
THAT'S ENTERPRISE.
AT LEAST WE SHOULD FIND
THE BLACK BOXES.
WITH WHAT?
WE HAVE NO RADIO, NOTHING
TO PICK UP THE BEACONS.
WHAT'S THE RANGE
IN OUR DISTRESS BEACON?
-IT'S OFFLINE.
-I'M TALKING ABOUT
THE PORTABLE ONE,
THE ONE IN THE AWAY KIT.
10 MILLION KILOMETERS,
MAYBE 20, BUT
I HIGHLY DOUBT THERE'D BE
A SHIP ANYWHERE CLOSE TO THAT.
WE'VE ONLY GOT 10 DAYS' WORTH
OF BREATHABLE AIR.
HOW FAR TO ECHO III?
AT IMPULSE?
A LOT MORE THAN 10 DAYS.
WELL, IF WE COULD GET
CLOSE ENOUGH FOR IT
TO PICK UP
OUR DISTRESS BEACON,
IT WOULD RELAY THE SIGNAL
BACK TO STARFLEET.
I'M AFRAID THE MATH
DOESN'T WORK OUT, COMMANDER.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE WEEKS,
MAYBE MONTHS,
FOR OUR SIGNAL
TO REACH ECHO III.
BY THE TIME STARFLEET GOT
A SHIP OUT HERE, WE'D BE...
WE'D BE LONG DEAD.
TUCKER: BUT AT LEAST
THEY'D FIND US.
THEY'D GET
THEIR SHUTTLEPOD BACK,
A COUPLE OF...
WELL-PRESERVED CORPSES.
-SIR.
-WHICH WAY?
REED: WHICH WAY TO WHAT?
ECHO III.
WHICH WAY TO ECHO III?
I TOLD YOU, IT'S TOO FAR!
DO YOU KNOW WHICH DIRECTION
IT IS OR DON'T YOU?
NAVIGATION IS DOWN.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I ASKED YOU!
YOU WANT ME TO GUESS?!
YOU COME FROM A LONG LINE
OF NAVY MEN
AND YOU GOT A REAL GOOD MEMORY!
LOOK HARD AT THOSE STARS,
FIND SOMETHING
THAT LOOKS FAMILIAR,
AND TELL ME WHICH WAY TO GO!
-SIR.
-THAT'S AN ORDER!
I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU HAVE A SEXTANT HANDY.
I LEFT IT WITH MY SLIDE RULE.
WELL?
THAT BLUE GIANT -- WE MAY HAVE
GONE BY IT; I'M NOT SURE.
TUCKER: THAT'S GOOD
ENOUGH FOR ME.
TAKE ONE MORE LOW PASS
OVER THE WRECKAGE.
AND THEN SET A COURSE.
SEE YOU AROUND, CAPTAIN.
PERSONAL LOG,
LIEUTENANT MALCOLM REED.
NOVEMBER 9, 2151.
BY THE TIME ANYONE HEARS THIS --
BY ANYONE, I SUPPOSE
I MEAN ANYONE HUMAN --
COMMANDER TUCKER AND I
WILL BE LONG DEAD.
IT'S MY INTENTION TO RECOUNT
THE EVENTS THAT LED TO
THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE
AND TO EXPRESS
MY DEEPEST FEELINGS
REGARDING MY SHORT BUT MEMORABLE
SERVICE WITH STARFLEET.
TELL THEM I'D LOVE
TO ADD MY TWO CENTS,
BUT I'M TRYING TO GET
A LITTLE WORK DONE.
[ RECORDING REWINDS ]
...SHORT BUT MEMORABLE SERVICE
WITH STARFLEET.
IN ORDER TO TEST THE TARGETING
SCANNERS ON SHUTTLEPOD ONE,
COMMANDER TUCKER
AND I HAD TO GET
AT LEAST 20,000 KILOMETERS
FROM ENTERPRISE.
DURING OUR THIRD TRIAL,
WE EXPERIENCED
A BRIEF BUT SIZABLE JOLT
AND, SHORTLY THEREAFTER,
REALIZED THAT OUR SENSOR ARRAY
HAD GONE OFFLINE.
TUCKER: THIS SENSOR ARRAY IS
MORE THAN OFFLINE.
IT'S TOTALLY FRIED.
[ RECORDING REWINDS ]
...THAT OUR SENSOR ARRAY
HAD GONE OFFLINE.
WE HAD NO CHOICE BUT TO HEAD
BACK TO THE ASTEROID FIELD
WHERE ENTERPRISE WAS INVOLVED
IN A MAPPING PROJECT.
WE FOUND THE SHIP...DESTROYED,
ITS DEBRIS STREWN
ACROSS A SQUARE KILOMETER
OF ONE OF THE LARGER ASTEROIDS.
HAD OUR SENSORS BEEN WORKING,
WE CERTAINLY WOULD HAVE DONE
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE TO DETERMINE
THE CAUSE OF THE DISASTER...
BUT AS IT WAS, WITH ONLY
A SHORT-RANGE DISTRESS BEACON
AND LIMITED AIR,
WE HAD NO ALTERNATIVE BUT
TO SET A COURSE FOR ECHO III,
WHERE, SOMEDAY, THIS VESSEL --
EVENTUALLY, THIS LOG --
WILL BE FOUND.
MAY GOD HAVE MERCY ON OUR SOULS.
WHY DON'T YOU CUT THE CRAP
AND GET BACK HERE AND HELP ME?
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE ME TO DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU COULD HOLD THIS FLASHLIGHT
OR TURN DOWN THE HEAT,
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
I'M JUST GETTING A LITTLE TIRED
OF LISTENING
TO ALL YOUR PESSIMISM.
IF THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU NEED ME TO DO,
I WOULD BE MORE
THAN HAPPY TO COMPLY,
BUT I'M AFRAID PESSIMISM
IS SIMPLY NOT
AN ACCURATE DESCRIPTION
OF MY LOG ENTRY.
I'M JUST BEING REALISTIC,
COMMANDER.
TUCKER: WE'VE GOT NINE DAYS.
WE'RE BOUND TO FIND
SOMEONE OUT HERE.
AT WARP, PERHAPS...
BUT AT IMPULSE?
VULCANS, KLINGONS, SULIBAN,
XYRILLIANS, ANDORIANS.
GOD KNOWS WHO'S GONNA BE
LURKING AROUND
THE NEXT PLANET WE RUN INTO.
BUT THAT'S JUST IT, SIR.
AT IMPULSE, WE'RE NOT LIKELY
TO BE RUNNING INTO ANY PLANETS,
NOT FOR AT LEAST
SIX OR SEVEN YEARS.
TUCKER: THEN SOMEBODY
CAN RUN INTO US.
YOU EVER THINK OF THAT?
OR SEE US ON THEIR SENSORS.
THE POSSIBILITIES ARE ENDLESS.
I'LL HEAT UP SOME RATIONS,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
YOU'D RATHER WAIT
UNTIL WE RUN INTO A VESSEL
SERVING PROPER MEALS.
RATIONS WILL BE FINE.
WHAT ARE YOU
IN THE MOOD FOR?
DEPENDS. WHAT ARE YOU SERVING?
AH. VEAL MARSALA.
CHILEAN SEA BASS.
MOO GOO GAI PAN.
ANY MEAT LOAF?
WITH GRAVY
AND MASHED POTATOES.
PERFECT.
KENTUCKY BOURBON.
AH, THE CAPTAIN WAS PLANNING
TO GIVE THAT TO SOMEBODY.
CAN'T REMEMBER WHO.
GUESS IT'S OURS NOW.
WHAT'S THAT?
THE SEA BASS.
ANY GOOD?
MMM.
IT'S LOVELY.
THANK YOU.
REED: CAPTAIN ARCHER CLAIMS
YOU TOLD HIM YOU WEREN'T
EVEN AWARE THAT I WAS
SERVING ON ENTERPRISE.
I FIND THAT DIFFICULT
TO BELIEVE,
CONSIDERING I WROTE YOU
TWICE IN THE WEEKS
PRIOR TO OUR DEPARTURE.
NOW, IT IS POSSIBLE THAT YOU
NEVER RECEIVED THOSE LETTERS.
YOU WERE, I BELIEVE,
IN THE PROCESS OF MOVING
BACK TO MALAYSIA AT THE TIME.
BUT YOU MUST HAVE SPOKEN TO
AUNT SHERRY DURING THAT PERIOD,
AND I KNOW
SHE RECEIVED MY LETTERS.
I WOULD HATE TO GO TO MY DEATH
THINKING THAT EITHER OF YOU
FELT I WAS TRYING TO AVOID --
TUCKER: MALCOLM!
YOU'VE BEEN AT IT
FOR HOURS NOW!
DON'T YOU THINK IT'S TIME
TO GIVE IT A REST?
AS I'M SURE YOU MUST HAVE HEARD,
THAT WAS MY ESTEEMED COLLEAGUE,
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER.
MR. TUCKER DOESN'T
SHARE MY BELIEF
THAT IT IS ESSENTIAL
TO SAY WHAT MUST BE SAID,
TO LEAVE A RECORD,
TIE UP LOOSE ENDS.
MR. TUCKER IS LABORING UNDER
THE FALSE HOPE THAT WE ARE GOING
TO BE MIRACULOUSLY RESCUED
BEFORE WE BOTH SUFFOCATE.
MR. AND MRS. REED...
I REALIZE THAT YOU'VE JUST BEGUN
A PERIOD OF MOURNING
AND THAT I'LL NEVER GET
AN ANSWER TO THIS QUESTION,
BUT I GOT TO ASK IT ANYWAY.
WAS MALCOLM ALWAYS THIS CYNICAL?
REED: IN A FEW DAYS, WHEN
THE REALITY OF THIS SITUATION
ACTUALLY BEGINS TO SINK IN,
YOU MIGHT VERY WELL DECIDE
YOU WANT TO RECORD
SOME LOGS OF YOUR OWN.
YOU HAVE MY WORD
I WILL NOT INTERRUPT YOU.
TUCKER: I JUST NEED
TO GET SOME SLEEP, MALCOLM!
IS THAT SO HARD TO UNDERSTAND?
REED: WE HAVE LESS THAN
NINE DAYS OF OXYGEN LEFT.
IT SEEMS A WASTE
TO USE IT UP SLEEPING.
IF I DON'T WASTE
SOME OXYGEN SLEEPING,
I'M GONNA START
GETTING REAL CRANKY.
AND YOU DON'T WANT
TO SPEND YOUR LAST NINE DAYS
COOPED UP WITH ME
WHEN I'M CRANKY...
SO TURN THAT THING OFF
AND GET SOME REST!
[ BEEPING ]
WE'RE BACK?
LIE STILL, LIEUTENANT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HOW DID WE --
ARCHER: YOU'RE A VERY
BRAVE MAN, MALCOLM.
COMMANDER TUCKER IS GONNA BE
FINE, THANKS TO YOU.
I'M AFRAID I DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
GET SOME REST;
THERE WILL BE PLENTY OF TIME
TO EXPLAIN WHAT
HAPPENED IN THE MORNING.
SUBCOMMANDER?
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
I'D FEEL A LOT BETTER
IF I KNEW WHAT WAS GOING ON.
CAPTAIN ARCHER WOULD
BE QUITE ANNOYED WITH ME
IF I TOLD YOU OF YOUR HEROICS.
I BELIEVE HE'S LOOKING FORWARD
TO DOING THAT HIMSELF
IN THE MORNING.
HEROICS?
I HAD NO IDEA
YOU COULD BE SO SELFLESS
IN THE FACE OF SUCH DANGER.
MOST MALES OF YOUR SPECIES WOULD
HAVE GIVEN IN TO THEIR FEAR.
WELL, SINCE YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY NOT
GOING TO TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED,
I SUPPOSE A SIMPLE "GOOD NIGHT"
WILL HAVE TO DO.
VULCANS COULD NEVER
IGNORE COURAGE...
AND THIS VULCAN...
WILL NEVER IGNORE
LIEUTENANT MALCOLM REED AGAIN.
WELL, I CAN'T SAY I'VE EVER...
IGNORED YOU, T'POL.
IS IT ALL RIGHT
IF I CALL YOU T'POL?
YES.
MAY I CALL YOU MALCOLM?
I SUPPOSE SO.
BUT, IF THE TRUTH BE KNOWN,
I'VE...NEVER MUCH CARED
FOR THE NAME MALCOLM.
ALWAYS SEEMED A BIT
TOO...STUFFY.
I THINK IT'S A LOVELY NAME.
MOL-KOM IS THE VULCAN WORD
FOR SERENITY.
WELL, THEN,
PERHAPS I WON'T CHANGE IT.
PITY, THOUGH.
I WAS RATHER GROWING FOND
OF THE NAME... "STINKY."
HMM.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU JUST DID THAT.
DID WHAT?
YOU SMILED.
I SAW YOU SMILE.
VULCANS DON'T SMILE.
THIS ONE DOES.
I SAW YOU.
YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
IT WAS WHEN I SAID "STINKY,"
WASN'T IT?
YOU SMILED WHEN I SAID "STINKY."
GOOD MORNING, STINKY.
IT'S A LOVELY DAY,
ISN'T IT, STINKY?
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ STATIC ]
-WHAT'S THAT?
-I GOT THE RECEIVER
WORKING, BUT THE TRANSMITTER'S
A LOST CAUSE.
WHO'S STINKY?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
TUCKER: YOU WERE TALKING
IN YOUR SLEEP.
KEPT CALLING FOR SOME GUY
NAMED STINKY.
[ GROANS ]
YOU REPAIRED THE RECEIVER?
WHAT IS THAT? IS IT A SHIP?
AH, THE RANGE IS VERY LIMITED.
IT'S PROBABLY
JUST WHITE NOISE --
THE SOUND OF THE GALAXY
LAUGHING AT US.
REED: WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
[ AIR HISSING ]
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT IT FELT A LITTLE LIKE
WHATEVER KNOCKED OUT
THE SENSOR ARRAY.
WE'RE LOSING ATMOSPHERE.
PRESSURE'S DOWN 8%.
TUCKER: HELP ME.
WE GOT TO FIND THE HOLE!
REED:
WITHOUT SENSORS, IT'S NOT GONNA
BE EASY TO LOCATE THE BREACH.
THEN USE YOUR EARS.
[ BEEPING ]
PRESSURE'S DOWN 22%.
THE DAMN HOLE'S TOO SMALL!
WHERE IS IT?!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TUCKER: IT'S NITROGEN
FOR THE COOLANT TANKS.
JUST GIVE ME A FEW SECONDS.
NOW LET'S FIND THAT LEAK.
I GOT IT. IT'S OVER HERE.
THERE'S ANOTHER ONE DOWN HERE.
PUT YOUR FINGER ON IT UNTIL WE
CAN FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO.
WE'VE GOT SOME VALVE SEALANT
IN STORAGE BIN THREE.
HAVE WE GOT ANYTHING
A LITTLE CLOSER?
UH...
DO YOU MIND PASSING ME
YOUR MEAT LOAF?
WHAT?
REED: I ASSUME YOU'VE
FINISHED WITH IT.
TUCKER: AND YOU CAME CLOSE
TO CRITICIZING
MY CHOICE OF CUISINE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
TUCKER: OBVIOUSLY, WHATEVER HIT
US WENT CLEAR THROUGH THE POD.
I'M AFRAID IT DID MORE
THAN JUST PUNCTURE
THE CABIN, COMMANDER.
ON ITS WAY OUT, IT WAS
KIND ENOUGH
TO RUPTURE ONE OF
THE O2 CYLINDERS.
GREAT.
HOW MUCH CLOSER
TO OBLIVION ARE WE?
[ SCOFFS ]
WE'VE GOT LESS THAN
TWO DAYS OF AIR LEFT.
THE SKIN OF THIS POD IS
DESIGNED TO DEFLECT A METEOR
FIVE TIMES THE SIZE
OF THIS HOLE.
WELL, IN THAT CASE, I'D GUESS
IT WASN'T A METEOR.
I WONDER IF SOMETHING
LIKE IT DESTROYED ENTERPRISE.
HMM. WE'LL NEVER KNOW.
ALWAYS THE OPTIMIST.
[ SCOFFS ]
WE HAVE 40 HOURS OF AIR LEFT.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT ME TO DO,
SIT HERE AND PLAN MY WEDDING?
TUCKER: I'M CONFIDENT THERE'LL
BE A CHARLES TUCKER IV ONE DAY.
REED: AH. WELL, MAYBE IT'S YOUR
WEDDING WE SHOULD BE PLANNING.
THAT'S ASSUMING WE CAN
FIND YOU A BRIDE
IN THE NEXT DAY AND A HALF.
ANY SUGGESTIONS?
THERE WAS A LITTLE BAR
IN MILL VALLEY
WHERE ALL THE STARFLEET
TRAINEES USED TO GO.
-AH, THE 602 CLUB.
-YOU KNOW IT?
[ CHUCKLES ] I WAS THERE MORE
TIMES THAN I CAN REMEMBER.
I MET THE GIRL OF MY DREAMS
MY FIRST FRIDAY NIGHT THERE.
-[ CHUCKLES ]
-SHE WAS THE ONE.
THERE WAS NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
WE HAD IT ALL FIGURED OUT --
WHERE WE'D LIVE,
HOW MANY KIDS WE'D HAVE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
AH, RUBY...
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO YOU?
RUBY?
YOU DON'T MEAN
THE WAITRESS RUBY?
YOU KNEW RUBY?
[ SIGHS ]
I KNEW HER MORE TIMES
THAN I CAN REMEMBER.
OUCH.
REED: SEEMS WE HAVE MORE
IN COMMON THAN WE THOUGHT.
YEAH.
WOULD ANOTHER HALF-DAY
BE WORTH FREEZING YOUR BUTT OFF?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
TUCKER: IF WE LOWER
THE THERMOSTAT IN HERE TO ABOUT
MINUS-5 CENTIGRADE,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO USE
THAT POWER TO ENHANCE
THE EFFICIENCY OF
THE ATMOSPHERE RECYCLERS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
OUR LAST 2 1/2 DAYS FREEZING,
VERSUS OUR LAST TWO DAYS
TOASTY WARM.
TSK. WHAT A DELIGHTFUL CHOICE.
I'D PICK FREEZING.
ANOTHER HALF-DAY'S
ANOTHER HALF-DAY.
FREEZING IT IS, THEN.
TUCKER: AND JUST WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
REED: AN OFFICER AT HIS BEST IS
ALWAYS WELL-GROOMED.
[ SHAVER BUZZING ]
NICE TO SEE YOU'RE DEVELOPING
A MORE POSITIVE ATTITUDE.
ACTUALLY, I WAS THINKING
ABOUT WHAT OUR CORPSES
WOULD LOOK LIKE WHEN THEY'RE
EVENTUALLY FOUND.
WITH NO AIR IN THE POD,
WE SHOULD REMAIN
IN FAIRLY GOOD CONDITION.
CHARMING.
BUT YOU'RE FORGETTING
ONE THING, MALCOLM.
-WHAT'S THAT?
-IF I REMEMBER
MY HONORS BIOLOGY COURSE
CORRECTLY, YOUR HAIR AND NAILS
KEEP GROWING FOR QUITE
A WHILE AFTER YOU'RE DEAD.
I'M PRETTY SURE
THAT INCLUDES YOUR BEARD.
[ TURNS OFF SHAVER ]
THANKS.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I'VE ANALYZED THE SCANS
WE TOOK OF THE TESNIAN SHIP
RIGHT BEFORE IT CRASHED.
I BELIEVE THEY WERE HIT
BY A MICRO-SINGULARITY.
YOU STILL CHASING GREMLINS?
T'POL: THIS IS
NO MYTH, CAPTAIN.
THREE OF THE SINGULARITIES
ALSO HIT ENTERPRISE.
THEY COLLIDED WITH OUR HULL
PLATING HERE, HERE, AND HERE.
ARCHER: YOU TELLING ME THESE
ARE TINY BLACK HOLES?
T'POL: THEY WERE.
THE DISPERSAL PATTERN SUGGESTS
THEY DISSIPATED ON IMPACT.
THIS COULD BE A SIGNIFICANT
DISCOVERY, CAPTAIN.
IF WE COULD GET
QUANTUM SENSOR READINGS OF
THE THREE IMPACT POINTS,
WE COULD AUTHENTICATE
OUR FINDINGS.
I'D BE A LITTLE LESS CONCERNED
WITH WINNING
THE NOBEL PRIZE RIGHT NOW
AND A LITTLE MORE CONCERNED
WITH TRIP AND MALCOLM.
THEIR SHUTTLEPOD DOESN'T HAVE
THE HULL PLATING WE DO.
THEY COULD BE IN
FOR A ROUGH RIDE
WHEN THEY GET BACK
TO THE ASTEROID FIELD.
BETTER HAIL THEM.
AGREE TO A NEW RENDEZVOUS POINT.
I NEVER INTENDED TO SUGGEST
THAT OUR CREW MEMBERS
WERE LESS IMPORTANT
THAN A SCIENTIFIC DISCOVERY,
EVEN ONE OF THIS
HISTORIC MAGNITUDE.
TIME'S A-WASTIN'.
[ BREATHING SHALLOWLY ]
MY DEAREST DEBORAH,
BY THIS TIME,
I'M CERTAIN YOU'VE LEARNED
OF THE TRAGEDY THAT BEFELL
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
YOU'VE ALSO UNDOUBTEDLY LEARNED
THAT MY COLLEAGUE,
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER, AND I
DID MANAGE TO SURVIVE
FOR A FEW DAYS AFTER
THE ACCIDENT.
IT'S DURING THAT BRIEF TIME
THAT I'VE CHOSEN
TO CORRESPOND WITH YOU.
ALTHOUGH OUR RELATIONSHIP
WAS...SHORT-LIVED
AND AT TIMES TUMULTUOUS,
I CAN'T HELP BUT PICTURE
YOUR BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
IT GIVES ME GREAT COMFORT.
THINK OF ME FROM TIME TO TIME.
CORDIALLY, MALCOLM.
[ STATIC ]
A SHIP?
IT'S A LITTLE MORE MODULATED
THAN THE LAST ONE,
BUT IT COULD BE JUST
A RANDOM GAMMA-RAY BURST.
OH.
MY DEAREST ROCHELLE,
BY THIS TIME, I'M CERTAIN YOU'VE
LEARNED OF THE TRAGEDY --
WOULDN'T IT BE EASIER JUST
TO RECORD ONE MESSAGE
AND THEN ADD
THE "DEAR WHOEVER" AFTERWARD?
THIS IS YOUR FIFTH
OR SIXTH IDENTICAL LETTER.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
THERE HAVE BEEN
SUBTLE DIFFERENCES.
I WOULD NEVER REFER TO ROCHELLE
AS HAVING A BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
WITH HER, IT WAS THE EYES.
TRAVIS AND HOSHI COULDN'T
HAVE BEEN MORE THAN...
24 OR 25 YEARS OLD.
IF THE CAPTAIN
WERE HERE WITH US NOW,
I WONDER IF HE'D FEEL GUILTY
ABOUT BRINGING THEM
ON THIS MISSION.
NOT FOR A MINUTE.
THEY DIED DOING WHAT THEY LOVED.
I DON'T REMEMBER HOSHI LOVING
MUCH ABOUT BEING IN DEEP SPACE.
AW, SHE WAS COMING ALONG.
SHE SAVED OUR ASSES
ON MORE THAN ONE OCCASION.
PLAN ON LETTING HER FAMILY KNOW
JUST HOW ESSENTIAL SHE WAS.
SOUNDS TO ME LIKE YOU DO HAVE
SOME LETTERS TO RECORD.
I'LL WAIT TO TELL THEM
IN PERSON.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU KNOW,
YOUR TREACLY OPTIMISM
IS BEGINNING TO GET JUST
A LITTLE BIT TIRESOME.
UNLIKE YOUR HEARTFELT LETTERS
OF FAREWELL
TO HALF THE GIRLS
IN SAN FRANCISCO?
AT LEAST I'M CAPABLE
OF ACCEPTING OUR FATE!
WE'RE GOING TO BE DEAD
IN ABOUT 33 HOURS!
WHETHER OUR BEARDS
CONTINUE TO GROW OR NOT
IS OF NO CONCERN TO ME!
WE WILL BE DEAD!
AND UNLESS SOME SHIP HAPPENS
TO CROSS OUR PATH,
OUR BEARDED BODIES
WILL BE DISCOVERED
IN ABOUT THREE OR FOUR YEARS!
IS THAT OPTIMISTIC ENOUGH
FOR YOU?!
TUCKER: WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM
WITH HAVING A LITTLE HOPE?
WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM
WITH FACING THE TRUTH?
YOU'RE A REGULAR
GRIM REAPER, MALCOLM.
ANYONE EVER TELL YOU THAT?
[ SCOFFS ]
WELL, IF THIS LITTLE TRIP
IS A DEATH SENTENCE,
THEN IT WOULD SEEM TO ME WE'RE
ENTITLED TO A LAST MEAL.
WHAT'LL IT BE?
I'M AFRAID OUR SELECTION
IS SOMEWHAT LIMITED.
REED: I'M NOT HUNGRY.
WELL, THEN, HOW 'BOUT A DRINK?
I DON'T DRINK ON DUTY.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WE'RE DEAD MEN, REMEMBER?
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
LIEUTENANT?
ARE YOU AFRAID
THE AUTOPSY WILL SHOW
YOUR BLOOD-ALCOHOL LEVEL
WAS TOO HIGH TO PILOT A SHUTTLE?
[ TUCKER SIGHS ]
LIVE A LITTLE.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
DO YOU REALLY THINK THAT'S GOING
TO PROVIDE ANY HEAT?
THE BOURBON WILL PROVIDE
THE HEAT.
THE CANDLE'S JUST FOR MOOD.
[ BREATH QUIVERING ]
TO THE BRAVE MEN AND WOMEN...
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
YOU KNOW THAT'S GONNA CONSUME
OXYGEN, DON'T YOU?
WE'LL PROBABLY BE DEAD
FIVE OR SIX MINUTES EARLIER
THAN WE WOULD HAVE BEEN.
I CAN LIVE WITH THAT.
ANYWAY, IT SEEMS TO ME,
AS FAR AS YOU'RE CONCERNED,
THE SOONER THE BETTER.
IS THAT REALLY HOW YOU SEE ME?
THE ETERNAL PESSIMIST?
THE GRIM REAPER?
I DON'T WANT TO DIE. WHAT MAKES
YOU THINK I WANT TO DIE?
TUCKER: BECAUSE EVER SINCE
WE SAW ENTERPRISE
SPREAD ACROSS THAT ASTEROID,
YOU'VE DONE NOTHING
BUT WRITE YOUR OWN OBITUARY.
I LOST NEARLY EVERYONE I CARED
ABOUT... ON THAT SHIP.
THOSE GIRLS I TALKED ABOUT --
ROCHELLE, DEBORAH, CATELIN --
NONE OF THEM WORKED OUT,
BECAUSE I COULD...
NEVER GET VERY CLOSE TO THEM.
NEVER GOT VERY CLOSE TO MY
FAMILY, EITHER, FOR THAT MATTER,
NOT THAT IT'S
ANY BUSINESS OF YOURS.
[ Voice breaking ] BUT WITH
THE CREW OF THE ENTERPRISE,
IT WAS DIFFERENT.
I WAS REALLY STARTING TO FEEL...
COMFORTABLE WITH THEM.
AND NOW THE ONLY ONE
THAT'S LEFT THINKS
I'M THE BLOODY ANGEL OF DEATH.
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
FIVE OR SIX MORE MINUTES
SOUNDS KIND OF NICE.
[ STATIC ]
[ Slurred ] DOES THAT SOUND
MODULATED ENOUGH FOR YOU?
[ Slurred ] MODULATED?
THE RADIO. HA HA!
OR IS IT JUST THE GALAXY
GIGGLING AT US AGAIN?
IT CAN GIGGLE ALL IT WANTS.
BUT THE GALAXY'S NOT GETTING
ANY OF OUR BOURBON.
NO.
HEY, UH... WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF T'POL, HUH?
DO YOU THINK SHE'S PRETTY?
T'POL? ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WELL, SHE'S A WOMAN, YOU KNOW?
I THINK SHE'S PRETTY.
YOU'VE HAD TOO MUCH TO DRINK.
[ SCOFFS ]
DON'T TELL ME YOU'VE
NEVER LOOKED AT HER,
YOU KNOW, IN THAT WAY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
NAH, SHE'S A VULCAN.
WELL... I THINK SHE'S PRETTY.
OH, GOD!
YOU EVER NOTICED HER BUM?
WHAT?
HER BUM.
[ REED CHUCKLES ]
SHE'S GOT AN AWFULLY NICE BUM.
[ CHUCKLING ]
TO SUBCOMMANDER T'POL.
[ LAUGHING ]
HA!
AWFULLY NICE! HA HA HA!
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
IT'S PROBABLY NOTHING, RIGHT?
IT'S DEFINITELY NOT NOTHING.
WELL, THEN THAT MEANS
IT'S SOMETHING.
WHAT IS IT?
WELL, IS IT SOMETHING
OR SOMEONE, BECAUSE
IF IT'S SOMEONE --
-SHH!
-SORRY.
DEFINITELY SOMEONE.
WE HAVE NO WAY
TO RESPOND, DO WE?
[ SIGHS ]
THIS IS LIKE THE PLANE FLYING
OVER THE DESERT ISLAND
IN A LOST-AT-SEA MOVIE.
-MALCOLM!
-SORRY.
HAPPY ENDINGS.
I MUST THINK HAPPY ENDINGS.
Shuttlepod One,
this is Enterprise.
Please respond.
THAT'S HOSHI!
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
DON'T BE SO PESSIMISTIC!
IT'S NOT IMPOSSIBLE!
IT'S HOSHI!
THEY'RE OKAY!
ENTERPRISE IS OKAY!
IT'S HOSHI!
Adjust your heading
to the new coordinates.
We will rendezvous in two days.
Commander, Lieutenant,
please respond.
"RENDEZVOUS!"
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL WORD.
WHAT'S WRONG?
THEY'RE STILL TWO DAYS AWAY.
AND WE ONLY HAVE A LITTLE MORE
THAN ONE DAY'S AIR LEFT.
AND NO WAY TO TELL THEM
TO GET HERE SOONER.
TUCKER: ARE YOU SURE
YOU GOT THE COORDINATES RIGHT?
REED: YES, NOT THAT IT MATTERS.
TUCKER: LIEUTENANT.
THEY'RE PROBABLY TRAVELING AT,
WHAT, WARP 2? WARP 3?
COMPARED TO THEM,
WE'RE LIKE A GARDEN SNAIL.
WHERE WE GO AND HOW FAST WE GET
THERE IS IRRELEVANT.
IF I PURGE THE CO2 FILTERS,
IT'LL GIVE US A LITTLE MORE AIR.
HOW MUCH?
AN HOUR'S WORTH?
PROBABLY LESS.
GREAT, SO WHEN THEY
REACH US IN TWO DAYS,
WE'LL HAVE BEEN OUT OF AIR
FOR...11 HOURS.
YOU EVER TRY HOLDING
YOUR BREATH FOR 11 HOURS?
A TRAIN LEAVES NEW YORK
AT 3 A.M. HEADING WEST,
WHILE ANOTHER LEAVES CHICAGO
AT 4:30 HEADING EAST.
[ SIGHS ]
I NEVER COULD FIGURE THOSE OUT.
ENTERPRISE IS GOING TO WONDER
WHY WE HAVEN'T RESPONDED, RIGHT?
MAYBE THEY'LL BE CONCERNED
AND INCREASE THEIR SPEED.
MAYBE, BUT IF WE REALLY WANT
TO GET THEM TO GO TO HIGH WARP,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO ATTRACT THEIR ATTENTION,
SOMETHING A LITTLE MORE DRAMATIC
THAN NOT ANSWERING THEIR HAILS.
CAN THEY SEE US
ON THEIR SENSORS?
TUCKER: TWO DAYS AWAY
AT WARP 3?
OH, THEY CAN SEE US,
MAYBE NOT TOO CLEARLY,
BUT WE SHOULD BE A NICE
LITTLE BLIP ON T'POL'S VIEWER.
THEN WE'VE GOT TO GET
THAT BLIP TO TELL THEM
TO PICK UP A LITTLE STEAM.
WHAT IF WE FIRED OUR WEAPONS?
THEY'RE NEARLY A QUARTER
OF A LIGHT-YEAR AWAY.
OUR PLASMA CANNONS HAVE A RANGE
OF LESS THAN 10 KILOMETERS.
IT WOULD ALL STILL LOOK
LIKE A SINGLE BLIP.
IT'S GONNA TAKE
A LOT MORE THAN THAT.
WHAT IF WE JETTISON
THE IMPULSE DRIVE?
WHAT GOOD WOULD THAT DO?
WELL, YOU COULD RIG
A SELF-DESTRUCT.
I IMAGINE THAT WOULD
MAKE QUITE AN EXPLOSION,
MAYBE EVEN BIG ENOUGH TO MAKE
THAT BLIP DO SOMETHING ODD.
NO, I CAN'T BLOW UP OUR ENGINE.
WE'D BE ADRIFT, DEAD IN SPACE.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN THAT
AND TRAVELING AT A SNAIL'S PACE?
I'M AN ENGINEER!
I WON'T BLOW UP OUR ONLY ENGINE!
THEN I'LL ASK YOU AGAIN --
EVER HOLD YOUR BREATH
FOR 11 HOURS?
I THINK I HAVE
SOME MICRO-DETONATORS
IN HERE SOMEWHERE.
[ SHIVERING ]
HOW DOES IT FEEL TO BE SLOWER
THAN A SNAIL?
I SAW A GREAT CARTOON ONCE.
THERE WERE THESE TWO SNAILS
SITTING ON THE BACK
OF A BIG OLD TURTLE,
AND ONE SNAIL TURNS
TO THE OTHER AND SAYS,
"HOLD ON, FRED.
HERE WE GO."
IF I'M RIGHT, I GET
THE REST OF THE BOURBON.
FINE.
LESS THAN 12 HOURS, YOU WIN.
MORE THAN 12...
AND IT'S MINE.
GO CHECK THE PRESSURE GAUGE.
YOU CHECK IT. I DON'T THINK
I CAN MOVE MY LEGS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE WE'VE BEEN
SITTING HERE THAT LONG.
TUCKER: COME ON,
LET'S HEAR IT.
HOW MUCH AIR IS LEFT?
10 HOURS.
THAT'S PROBABLY THE LAST BET
I'LL EVER MAKE,
AND I WON.
I SHOULD FEEL LIKE
CELEBRATING, SHOULDN'T I?
THE WHISKEY'S YOURS.
NOW, WHY DON'T YOU GIVE US
A TOAST BEFORE YOU DRINK IT?
10 HOURS FOR TWO MEN.
IF THERE WERE ONLY ONE OF US,
HE'D HAVE 20 HOURS, WOULDN'T HE?
HUH! GREAT IDEA.
WHY DON'T YOU...
CLIMB UP INTO THE AIRLOCK...
AND SEAL YOURSELF IN?
THAT'S JUST WHAT I WAS THINKING.
ANY LAST WORDS
YOU WANT ME TO PASS ALONG?
YEAH.
[ GROANS ]
TELL CAPTAIN ARCHER
THAT IT WAS ONE HELL
OF AN HONOR SERVING WITH HIM.
REED: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE DON'T KNOW
WHETHER OR NOT THEY SAW
OUR LITTLE DISPLAY
OF PYROTECHNICS...
BUT EITHER WAY,
THIS'LL DOUBLE YOUR CHANCES.
REED: YOU'RE CRAZY!
NOW GET DOWN FROM THERE!
TUCKER: SIT DOWN, LIEUTENANT.
IF ANYONE SHOULD GO UP IN THERE,
IT SHOULD BE ME!
YOU'RE THE CHIEF ENGINEER!
TUCKER: I'M ALSO
IN CHARGE OF DECIDING
WHO'S GOING INTO THIS AIRLOCK.
DO I MAKE MYSELF CLEAR?
COMMANDER.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
KILL ME?
IT'S SET TO STUN.
I DON'T WANT TO USE IT,
BUT I WILL.
PUT IT DOWN!
-GO TO HELL!
-OH!
STOP TRYING TO BE A HERO.
IT DOESN'T SUIT YOU.
REED: WHAT WOULD YOU KNOW
ABOUT BEING A HERO?!
IT TAKES NOTHING BUT A COWARD TO
CRAWL UP INSIDE A HOLE TO DIE!
THEN GO AHEAD AND SHOOT ME,
BUT YOU BETTER HOPE
WE DON'T MAKE IT,
BECAUSE IF WE SURVIVE,
THE FIRST THING I'M GONNA DO
IS BUST YOUR ASS BACK
TO CREWMAN SECOND CLASS
FOR INSUBORDINATION!
BE MY GUEST!
I COULD USE A LITTLE LESS
RESPONSIBILITY!
NOW GET DOWN HERE!
WHO THE HELL
DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?!
YOUR ARMORY OFFICER
AND PERHAPS YOUR FRIEND!
FRIENDS DON'T
SHOOT EACH OTHER!
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT A DOCTOR,
BUT I'M PRETTY SURE
YOU USE UP A LOT MORE OXYGEN
WHEN YOU SHOUT LIKE THAT!
SO WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
THAT YOU'D RATHER
HAVE ENTERPRISE
FIND THE TWO OF US DEAD IN HERE?
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I'M SAYING.
IF THERE'S ONE CHANCE
IN A THOUSAND
THAT THEY SAW
OUR IMPULSE DRIVE EXPLODE,
THAT THEY INCREASED
THEIR SPEED,
I'LL TAKE THAT CHANCE.
I'VE INVESTED
FAR TOO MUCH TIME
TRYING TO FIGURE YOU OUT,
MR. TUCKER.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO ACCEPT THAT IT
WAS ALL FOR NOTHING.
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
WE'RE BACK.
-HOW DID --
-EASY, MALCOLM.
YOU FELLAS HAD A NICE LITTLE
BOUT WITH HYPOTHERMIA.
THE COMMANDER.
HE'S GONNA BE FINE.
IT TOOK NEARLY THREE HOURS
TO GET YOUR BODY TEMPERATURES
BACK TO NORMAL.
YOU MUST HAVE SEEN
THE EXPLOSION.
ARCHER: HARD TO MISS.
YOU KNOW, YOU GUYS ONLY HAD
TWO OR THREE HOURS OF AIR LEFT.
YOU DON'T SAY.
WE SAW DEBRIS FROM ENTERPRISE
ON ONE OF THE ASTEROIDS.
WE ASSUMED --
WE THOUGHT YOU WERE ALL...
I'LL TELL YOU
ALL ABOUT IT IN THE MORNING.
RIGHT NOW, THE DOCTOR NEEDS
TO WARM YOU UP A FEW DEGREES.
SUBCOMMANDER.
YES?
ISN'T THERE SOMETHING
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO SAY TO ME?
ABOUT WHAT?
HEROICS.
SOMETHING ABOUT HEROICS.
GOOD NIGHT, LIEUTENANT.
TRIP?
MIND IF I CALL YOU TRIP?
SLEEP WELL, MY FRIEND.