T'POL: THIS TEXTBOOK
IS WHAT YOU WANTED ME TO SEE?
ARCHER: NOT EXACTLY.
LOOK FAMILIAR?
THIS WAS MY FIRST
ASTRONOMY BOOK.
MY FATHER GOT IT FOR ME
ON MY 8th BIRTHDAY.
I USED TO STARE AT THE COVER
FOR HOURS.
THE ARACHNID NEBULA.
WHO'D EVER HAVE THOUGHT
I WOULD GET TO SEE IT IN PERSON?
IT'S LESS
THAN A LIGHT-YEAR AWAY.
WE'LL BE THERE IN A FEW HOURS.
T'POL: "FROM THE LIBRARY
OF ADMIRAL JONNY ARCHER"?
ARCHER: I HAD HIGH HOPES
WHEN I WAS A KID.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
YES?
REED: Sir, there's a ship
approaching at half impulse.
They're hailing us.
ARCHER: DO YOU KNOW WHO IT IS?
REED: Hoshi says they're
using a Vulcan frequency.
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER: DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
ANY VULCAN SHIP I'VE EVER SEEN.
T'POL: THIS CLASS OF VESSEL
HASN'T
BEEN USED FOR A LONG TIME.
HOSHI: THEY'RE HAILING US AGAIN.
TAVIN: IS THIS THE EARTH VESSEL
ENTERPRISE?
ARCHER: IT IS.
I'M CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
TAVIN: MY NAME IS TAVIN,
CAPTAIN OF THE VAHKLAS.
IT'S VERY GOOD TO MEET YOU.
SINGER:
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: I GET THE FEELING
YOU WEREN'T SENT OUT HERE
BY THE HIGH COMMAND.
TAVIN: NOT QUITE.
WE'RE A CIVILIAN SHIP.
ARCHER:
WHAT BRINGS YOU OUT THIS FAR?
TAVIN: I SUPPOSE YOU COULD SAY
WE'RE ON A MISSION
OF EXPLORATION.
ARCHER: FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
VULCANS AREN'T THAT INTERESTED
IN EXPLORING.
TAVIN: WE'RE NOT
TYPICAL VULCANS.
I'D BE HAPPY TO EXPLAIN,
BUT FIRST, I'D LIKE
TO ASK A FAVOR.
ARCHER: CERTAINLY.
TAVIN: OUR PROPULSION
AND LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS
ARE IN NEED OF REPAIR.
WE'D BE GRATEFUL FOR ANY
ASSISTANCE YOU COULD OFFER.
ARCHER:
WE'LL SEE WHAT WE CAN DO.
TAVIN:
WE'VE NOTICED THE HIGH COMMAND
LOOKING OVER OUR SHOULDERS
ON SEVERAL OCCASIONS, AS WELL.
ARCHER: HA HA!
WELL, THAT'S GOOD TO KNOW.
I WAS STARTING TO THINK
THEY'D SINGLED US OUT.
TAVIN: HMM.
ARCHER: OUR CHEF'S HAD A LOT
OF EXPERIENCE LATELY
PREPARING VULCAN DISHES.
T'POL SAYS HE'S GOTTEN
PRETTY GOOD AT IT.
TAVIN: UH, WHAT IS THAT?
ARCHER: OH,
IT'S CALLED "CHICKEN."
TAVIN: OH, UH...MAY I?
ARCHER: OF COURSE.
IT'S, UM...MEAT, YOU KNOW.
TAVIN: IT LOOKS DELICIOUS.
ARCHER: SO...
WHEN DID YOU LEAVE VULCAN?
TAVIN: UH, EIGHT YEARS AGO.
TOLARIS: AND IN THOSE
8 YEARS, WE'VE EXPERIENCED MORE
THAN MOST VULCANS
WILL IN THEIR LIFETIME.
ARCHER:
YOU SAID YOU WERE EXPLORERS?
TAVIN: YES, BUT IT'S NOT
SPACE WE'RE EXPLORING--
IT'S OURSELVES.
MMM!
T'POL: YOU'RE V'TOSH KA'TUR.
ARCHER: I'M SORRY?
TAVIN:
"VULCANS WITHOUT LOGIC."
IT'S A NAME THE ELDERS
GIVE TO ANYONE
WHO DISAGREES WITH
THE ANCESTRAL TEACHINGS,
BUT IT'S NOT ENTIRELY ACCURATE.
WE HAVEN'T ABANDONED LOGIC.
WE'VE SIMPLY LEARNED TO EXIST
WITHOUT THE NEED
TO CONTINUALLY REPRESS
OUR EMOTIONS.
IT'S TAKEN
YEARS OF EXPERIMENTATION,
BUT WE'VE MANAGED TO FIND
A BALANCE BETWEEN THE TWO.
T'POL: THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
TOLARIS: HERE WE ARE.
TAVIN: LOGIC IS AN ESSENTIAL
PART OF VULCAN EXISTENCE.
BUT IT HAS TO COMPLEMENT
EMOTIONS, NOT EXCLUDE THEM.
TOLARIS: YOU MUST KNOW
A GREAT DEAL ABOUT EMOTION.
YOU LIVE ON A HUMAN STARSHIP.
THAT'S NOT SOMETHING
THAT MANY VULCANS
WOULD BE COMFORTABLE WITH.
T'POL:
I AM HERE AS AN OBSERVER.
TOLARIS: I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO OFFEND YOU.
T'POL: I'M NOT CAPABLE
OF FEELING OFFENSE.
ARCHER: MY CHIEF ENGINEER
TELLS ME
YOUR REPAIRS ARE GONNA TAKE
THREE OR FOUR DAYS.
WE WERE GOING TO USE THAT TIME
TO EXPLORE THE NEBULA,
IF YOU DON'T MIND TAGGING ALONG.
TAVIN: NOT AT ALL.
ARCHER: HUH.
TUCKER: I'VE NEVER SEEN
AN ENGINE THIS FAR GONE.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO SWAP OUT
EVERY PLASMA RELAY
IN YOUR REACTOR.
KOV: THERE ARE A LOT
OF WOMEN ON YOUR SHIP.
TUCKER:
NEARLY A THIRD OF THE CREW.
KOV:
IS IT TRUE YOU MATE YEAR-ROUND
WITH ANY OF THEM YOU CHOOSE?
TUCKER: YOU HAVEN'T
BEEN AROUND HUMANS TOO MUCH,
HAVE YOU?
KOV: YOU ARE THE FIRST
WE'VE MET.
BUT I'VE HEARD A LOT OF STORIES.
YOUR PEOPLE INDULGE
THEIR PASSIONS.
DO YOU REALLY EAT
SIX MEALS A DAY?
TUCKER: MORE LIKE THREE.
KOV: AND WHAT ABOUT SLEEP?
I UNDERSTAND YOU SPEND
MORE THAN HALF THE DAY IN BED.
TUCKER: EIGHT HOURS.
WE SLEEP FOR EIGHT HOURS.
IN MY CASE, ABOUT SIX.
WHEN WE'RE THROUGH HERE,
MAYBE WE CAN GET A BITE TO EAT.
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO CLEAR UP
SOME OF YOUR, UM...
MISCONCEPTIONS.
KOV:
OH, I'D LIKE THAT, COMMANDER.
TUCKER: EH, CALL ME TRIP.
T'POL: THEY'VE ASKED
FOR ANY MEDICAL SUPPLIES
WE CAN SPARE
AND A THOUSAND LITERS
OF PLASMA COOLANT.
ARCHER: WELL, THAT SHOULDN'T
BE A PROBLEM.
T'POL: TAVIN HAS ALSO REQUESTED
THE RECIPE FOR CHICKEN MARSALA.
ARCHER: TELL HIM CHEF'S RECIPES
ARE USUALLY CLASSIFIED,
BUT WE'LL MAKE AN EXCEPTION
IN THIS CASE.
I THOUGHT...
YOU'D BE SPENDING
A LITTLE MORE TIME
GETTING TO KNOW OUR GUESTS.
T'POL: I'VE BEEN BUSY.
ARCHER: SEEMS TO ME LIKE
YOU'VE BEEN BUSY AVOIDING THEM.
I CAN UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU MIGHT NOT APPROVE
OF WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO DO,
BUT FOR ALL WE KNOW,
THEY'RE ON TO SOMETHING.
T'POL: THAT'S UNLIKELY.
ARCHER: IS IT?
EIGHT YEARS.
THAT'S A PRETTY GOOD
TRACK RECORD.
T'POL: JUST BECAUSE THEY SMILE
AND EAT CHICKEN
DOESN'T MEAN THEY'VE LEARNED
TO MASTER THEIR EMOTIONS.
ARCHER: MAYBE I'M
JUST RELIEVED TO FINALLY MEET
SOME VULCANS WHO AREN'T
GIVING ME A HARD TIME.
THEN AGAIN...
IF THEY HAVE FOUND
THIS BALANCE...
T'POL: THEY'RE NOT
THE FIRST ONES
TO ATTEMPT THIS, CAPTAIN.
OTHERS HAVE TRIED
TO REINTEGRATE THEIR EMOTIONS.
THEY ALL FAILED.
WHAT THEY'RE DOING IS DANGEROUS.
ARCHER:
UNLESS MY INSTINCTS ARE WAY OFF,
THEY DON'T SEEM
VERY DANGEROUS TO ME.
BUT I COULD BE WRONG.
I CAN'T ORDER YOU
TO SPEND TIME WITH THEM,
BUT I WOULD ENCOURAGE YOU
TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND.
[LIQUID POURING]
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
TOLARIS: SO THIS IS
THE MESS HALL.
T'POL: IT IS.
TOLARIS: THE CREW MUST NOT
HAVE MUCH OF AN APPETITE.
T'POL: MOST OF THEM ARE ASLEEP.
IT'S QUITE LATE.
TOLARIS: COULD YOU SHOW ME
HOW TO OPERATE THIS?
T'POL: WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
TOLARIS: I'M NOT SURE.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH EXPERIENCE
WITH HUMAN FOOD.
WHAT'S THAT?
T'POL: MINT TEA.
TOLARIS: THAT'LL BE FINE.
T'POL: MINT TEA. HOT.
[LIQUID POURING]
TOLARIS: THANK YOU.
IT HAS A LOT OF FLAVOR.
T'POL: YOU CAN TRY
SOMETHING ELSE.
TOLARIS: NO, IT'S FINE.
I--I'M JUST SURPRISED.
DO YOU LIKE THE TASTE?
T'POL: THEIR SELECTION
OF VULCAN BEVERAGES IS LIMITED.
TOLARIS: BUT IT
CAN MAKE VULCAN TEA.
T'POL: YES.
TOLARIS: INTERESTING.
T'POL: UNLESS YOU NEED
FURTHER ASSISTANCE...
TOLARIS: HOW LONG
HAVE YOU LIVED AMONG HUMANS?
T'POL: I SPENT TWO YEARS
AT THE VULCAN CONSULATE ON EARTH
AND SEVEN MONTHS
ON "ENTERPRISE."
TOLARIS: THAT'S A LONG TIME
AWAY FROM HOME.
LIVING HERE HAS OBVIOUSLY
AFFECTED YOU IN WAYS
THAT YOU DON'T REALIZE.
T'POL: YOU MAY BE RIGHT.
ON OCCASION,
I ALSO DRINK CHAMOMILE TEA.
TOLARIS:
AND YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR--
A CONCEPT THAT MOST VULCANS
CAN'T SEEM TO GRASP.
T'POL: YOU ARE EASILY AMUSED.
TOLARIS:
THERE'S THAT HUMOR AGAIN.
I'M CURIOUS,
WHY DO YOU STAY HERE?
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER NEEDS
A SCIENCE OFFICER.
TOLARIS:
IS THAT THE ONLY REASON?
MAYBE YOU'RE MORE ATTACHED
TO THESE PEOPLE
THAN YOU'D CARE TO ADMIT.
T'POL:
WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
YOUR EMOTIONS ARE MUCH CLOSER TO
THE SURFACE THAN OTHER VULCANS'.
THEY'RE EASIER TO READ.
T'POL: I HAVE YET TO MEDITATE
THIS EVENING.
PERHAPS THAT'S
WHAT YOU'RE SENSING.
TOLARIS: THIS MAY SURPRISE YOU,
BUT WE STILL MEDITATE.
THE BALANCE BETWEEN
EMOTION AND LOGIC
REQUIRES CONSTANT DISCIPLINE.
T'POL: SO YOU'VE SAID.
YOU AND YOUR COLLEAGUES
HAVE CHOSEN A RECKLESS PATH.
TOLARIS: HAVE WE?
T'POL: HISTORY'S SHOWN
THAT VULCANS WHO ATTEMPT
TO EMBRACE THEIR EMOTIONS
OFTEN REVERT
TO THEIR PRIMAL NATURE.
TOLARIS: THAT'S A MYTH.
PROPAGANDA FROM 5,000 YEARS AGO.
OUR PRIMAL NATURE, T'POL,
IS NOT AS DANGEROUS
AS YOU THINK.
COMMANDER TUCKER SUGGESTS
THAT I TRY SOMETHING
CALLED PIZZA.
WOULD YOU CARE TO JOIN ME?
T'POL: I'VE ALREADY EATEN.
ANOTHER TIME, PERHAPS.
REED:
IS IT WHAT YOU IMAGINED, SIR?
ARCHER:
PICTURES DON'T DO IT JUSTICE.
TRAVIS: IT'S BIG.
OVER EIGHT BILLION KILOMETERS
IN DIAMETER.
ARCHER: EIGHT BILLION?
ARE YOU SURE?
TRAVIS: ACCORDING TO SENSORS.
ARCHER: MY ASTRONOMY BOOK
SAID IT WAS ONLY 6 1/2.
HOSHI: WE'LL HAVE
TO SEND OUR READINGS
TO THE PUBLISHER SO THEY CAN
PUT OUT A REVISED EDITION.
ARCHER: HOW LONG WOULD IT TAKE
TO CHART THAT THING?
T'POL: SEVERAL WEEKS.
TAVIN: MY VESSEL IS EQUIPPED
WITH TRANSLINEAR SENSORS.
WE COULD HELP
YOU COMPLETE THE SURVEY
A GOOD DEAL QUICKER.
ARCHER: WE SHOULD
HAVE SOMEONE ON YOUR SHIP
TO MONITOR THE DATA.
WOULD YOU
MIND WORKING FROM THERE?
T'POL: NO.
ARCHER: GLAD YOU DROPPED BY.
TAKE US IN, TRAVIS.
TOLARIS: LOOK AT THAT.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING SO BEAUTIFUL.
YOU'D PROBABLY CONSIDER THAT
AN EMOTIONAL REACTION.
T'POL: NOT NECESSARILY.
IT IS AESTHETICALLY PLEASING.
TOLARIS: "PLEASING"?
COMING FROM YOU,
THAT'S PRACTICALLY AN OUTBURST.
T'POL: IT'S CURIOUS THAT PEOPLE
WHO REJECT SURAK'S TEACHINGS
WOULD DISPLAY HIS LIKENESS.
TOLARIS: WE DON'T
REJECT HIS TEACHINGS.
WE SIMPLY DISAGREE
WITH HOW THEY'RE INTERPRETED.
HAVE YOU READ HIS ORIGINAL TEXT?
HE NEVER INTENDED FOR US
TO PURGE OUR EMOTIONS.
HE WANTED US TO MASTER THEM
AND THEN CAREFULLY
INTEGRATE THEM INTO OUR LIVES.
T'POL: I DOUBT MANY
WOULD AGREE WITH YOU.
TOLARIS:
THAT DOESN'T MEAN WE'RE WRONG.
T'POL: WHAT DID YOU DO
ON VULCAN BEFORE YOU LEFT?
TOLARIS: I TAUGHT LITERATURE
AT THE SHIRKAR ACADEMY.
T'POL: YOU GAVE UP A GREAT DEAL
TO WANDER THE GALAXY
IN A TRANSPORT.
TOLARIS: I DON'T HAVE
ANY REGRETS.
I ALWAYS KNEW
THERE HAD TO BE MORE TO LIFE
THAN JUST LOGIC AND REASON.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER FELT THAT WAY?
T'POL: NOT RECENTLY.
TOLARIS: BUT YOU DID ONCE?
T'POL: ONCE.
I SHOULD TAKE THESE READINGS
BACK TO "ENTERPRISE."
TOLARIS: T'POL...
YOU SAID THAT YOU
MEDITATED EACH NIGHT.
TONIGHT...DON'T.
SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND YOUR DREAMS
WILL BE FAR MORE INTERESTING.
YOU'RE A SCIENTIST.
CONSIDER IT AN EXPERIMENT.
TUCKER: WHERE'D YOU HEAR THAT?
KOV: A VULCAN ANTHROPOLOGIST
TOLD ME HE'D SEEN THE RITUAL
DURING AN EARTH EXPEDITION.
TUCKER: THEY'RE NOT TRYING
TO KILL THE QUARTERBACK.
THEY'RE JUST TRYING TO KEEP HIM
FROM THROWING THE BALL
OR RUNNING WITH IT.
IT'S ONLY A GAME,
NOT A FIGHT TO THE DEATH.
KOV: I SEE.
TUCKER: YOU MUST THINK
WE'RE A BUNCH OF BARBARIANS.
KOV: YOUR SPECIES
DOES HAVE A REPUTATION,
BUT I'VE ALWAYS SUSPECTED
THE STORIES WERE EXAGGERATED.
TUCKER: WELL, I HOPE
YOU'LL TELL ALL YOUR FRIENDS,
SET THE RECORD STRAIGHT.
KOV: GLADLY.
TUCKER: THERE'S, UH...
SOMETHING I'VE ALWAYS WONDERED
ABOUT VULCANS.
MAYBE YOU COULD
CLEAR IT UP FOR ME.
KOV: PLEASE.
TUCKER: IT'S KIND OF PERSONAL.
KOV: GO AHEAD.
TUCKER: WELL, I'VE LEARNED
ABOUT YOUR MARRIAGE CUSTOMS,
HOW YOUR PARENTS
ARRANGE THE WHOLE THING
WHEN YOU'RE YOUNG,
STUFF LIKE THAT,
BUT WHAT ABOUT...
YOU KNOW.
KOV: AH, YOU MEAN SEX!
TUCKER: IT'S NOT A TOPIC
I'VE HEARD VULCANS DISCUSS.
KOV: WELL, WE DO HAVE IT, IF
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE ASKING.
[REED CLEARS THROAT]
REED:
AM I INTERRUPTING ANYTHING?
KOV: NO. PLEASE
JOIN US, MISTER...
REED: REED. MALCOLM REED.
KOV: KOV. WE WERE JUST
DISCUSSING
VULCAN MATING RITUALS.
REED: OH.
KOV: MOST OF MY PEOPLE
ARE EXTREMELY UNCOMFORTABLE
TALKING ABOUT SUCH THINGS.
SO MANY INHIBITIONS.
VULCAN MALES ARE DRIVEN TO MATE
ONCE EVERY SEVEN YEARS.
TUCKER: SEVEN YEARS?
REED: FRIGHTENING.
KOV: OVER THE PAST FEW YEARS,
WE'VE BEEN DEVELOPING METHODS
TO ACCELERATE THE MATING CYCLE.
TUCKER: YOU UP FOR SECONDS?
KOV: I'VE HAD ENOUGH, THANK YOU.
BACK TO WORK.
A PLEASURE MEETING YOU,
MR. REED.
REED: LIKEWISE.
[REED CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
[CONSOLE BEEPS]
HOSHI: SIR, I'M PICKING UP
A TRANSMISSION
FROM "ECHO III."
ARCHER: STARFLEET?
HOSHI: IT'S ADMIRAL FORREST.
ARCHER:
I'LL TAKE IT IN MY READY ROOM.
ADMIRAL FORREST,
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
FORREST: YOU, TOO, JON.
I UNDERSTAND YOU HAVE GUESTS.
ARCHER: A VULCAN CREW.
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
FORREST: I GOT A CALL
FROM AMBASSADOR SOVAL
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
THEY'RE AWARE THAT YOU'VE
DOCKED WITH THE VAHKLAS,
AND THEY HAVE A FAVOR TO ASK.
ARCHER: A FAVOR FROM ME?
A MINISTER AT THE HIGH COMMAND
HAS A SON ON THAT SHIP--
AN ENGINEER NAMED KOV.
HAVE YOU MET HIM?
ARCHER: I DON'T THINK SO.
FORREST: WELL, APPARENTLY,
THE TWO OF THEM
HAD A FALLING OUT
ABOUT 9, 10 YEARS AGO.
HIS FATHER'S TRIED TO CONTACT
HIM SEVERAL TIMES SINCE THEN,
BUT KOV WON'T RESPOND.
ARCHER:
WHAT DO THEY WANT ME TO DO?
FORREST: I HEAR THESE AREN'T
YOUR GARDEN-VARIETY VULCANS.
CAN I ASSUME
YOU'RE ON FRIENDLY TERMS?
ARCHER: YES.
FORREST:
KOV'S FATHER IS DYING, JON.
HE'D LIKE TO SPEAK
WITH HIS SON.
MAYBE YOU CAN
ENCOURAGE HIM SOMEHOW.
ARCHER:
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
FORREST: THE HIGH COMMAND
LET YOU KEEP
YOUR SCIENCE OFFICER.
IT WOULDN'T HURT
TO RETURN THE FAVOR.
ARCHER: UNDERSTOOD.
FORREST: KEEP ME POSTED.
TOLARIS: OUR PRIMAL NATURE
ISN'T AS DANGEROUS
AS YOU THINK.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION,
LAUGHTER]
[SLOW JAZZ PLAYING]
TOLARIS: DO YOU LIKE THE TASTE?
YOU MUST HAVE LEARNED
A GREAT DEAL ABOUT EMOTION.
[JAZZ CONTINUES]
WHY DO YOU STAY HERE?
[MUSIC VOLUME INCREASES]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[MUSIC TRANSITIONS TO FREE JAZZ]
[MUSIC STOPS]
PHLOX: HMM.
THIS IS MORE
THAN A SIMPLE HEADACHE.
YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE'S ELEVATED,
AND I'M READING UNUSUALLY HIGH
SYNAPTIC ACTIVITY.
IT DOESN'T APPEAR TO BE A VIRUS
OR A BACTERIAL INFECTION.
I'D LIKE TO RUN A CRANIAL SCAN
JUST TO BE SAFE.
T'POL: THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY.
PHLOX: IT'LL ONLY TAKE A MOMENT.
T'POL: I BELIEVE I CAN EXPLAIN
MY SYMPTOMS.
LAST NIGHT,
I NEGLECTED TO MEDITATE
BEFORE I WENT TO SLEEP.
AS A RESULT, I AWOKE FEELING...
AGITATED.
ALL I NEED IS AN INJECTION
OF INAPROVALINE.
25 MILLIGRAMS SHOULD SUFFICE.
PHLOX: VERY WELL, DOCTOR.
IT'S, UH, NOT LIKE YOU
TO STRAY FROM YOUR ROUTINE.
THIS WOULDN'T HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH OUR VISITORS?
YOU'VE BEEN SPENDING QUITE A BIT
OF TIME ON THEIR SHIP.
T'POL: I'VE BECOME
ACQUAINTED WITH ONE OF THEM.
HE SUGGESTED THAT MY DREAMS
MIGHT BE MORE INTERESTING
IF I DIDN'T MEDITATE.
PHLOX: AND?
T'POL: HE WAS WRONG.
THEY WERE UNSETTLING.
IT WAS A FOOLISH THING TO DO.
PHLOX: NOTHING THAT
A LITTLE, UH, INAPROVALINE
CAN'T CURE.
I CAN UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU'D BE
INTRIGUED BY THEIR PHILOSOPHY.
MAYBE YOU SHOULDN'T BE
SO QUICK TO DISMISS IT
AFTER ONE BAD EXPERIENCE.
T'POL: THERE ARE TOO MANY RISKS.
IT WOULD BE UNWISE TO CONTINUE.
PHLOX: YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
BUT, UH, IF YOU DO DECIDE
TO EXPERIMENT FURTHER,
KEEP IN MIND THAT THEY'VE
BEEN WORKING ON THIS
FOR A NUMBER OF YEARS.
YOU'VE ONLY KNOWN THEM
FOR TWO DAYS.
GO SLOWLY, HMM?
T'POL: THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
KOV: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: PLEASE HAVE A SEAT.
KOV: THE REPAIRS
TO OUR PROPULSION SYSTEM
ARE GOING WELL.
MR. TUCKER'S BEEN VERY HELPFUL.
ARCHER: THAT'S GOOD TO HEAR.
KOV: IS THERE A PROBLEM?
ARCHER: I CALLED YOU HERE
TO PASS ALONG A MESSAGE...
FROM YOUR FATHER.
KOV: YOU SPOKE WITH HIM?
ARCHER: ACTUALLY, IT CAME
THROUGH A VULCAN AMBASSADOR.
I'M SORRY TO BE THE ONE
TO TELL YOU THIS,
BUT YOUR FATHER IS VERY ILL.
HE WANTS YOU TO CONTACT HIM
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
IF YOU'D LIKE, MY COMM OFFICER
CAN ARRANGE THE TRANSMISSION.
KOV: IT'S A KIND OFFER,
BUT I'LL DEAL WITH THIS MYSELF.
THANKS FOR THE MESSAGE.
ARCHER: I KNOW IT'S NONE
OF MY BUSINESS, BUT...
DO YOU PLAN ON CONTACTING HIM?
KOV: THE LAST TIME
I SPOKE WITH MY FATHER,
HE SAID I'D BROUGHT SHAME
TO 15 GENERATIONS OF OUR FAMILY.
ARCHER: HE'S DYING, KOV.
KOV: IF IT ISN'T
TOO MUCH TROUBLE,
WOULD YOU PLEASE
SEND A MESSAGE BACK FOR ME?
TELL HIM THAT WE SAID GOOD-BYE
A LONG TIME AGO.
TOLARIS: GOOD MORNING.
CHAMOMILE?
T'POL: THANK YOU.
TOLARIS: HOW DID IT GO?
T'POL: THE LATERAL SENSORS
WERE OUT OF ALIGNMENT.
I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE
TO SCAN THE DISODIUM LAYER.
TOLARIS: I MEAN LAST NIGHT.
DID YOU TAKE MY ADVICE?
T'POL: YES.
TOLARIS: AND YOUR DREAMS?
T'POL: I'D RATHER
NOT DISCUSS THEM.
TOLARIS: IT WILL GET EASIER.
TONIGHT WILL BE LESS DISTURBING.
T'POL: I PLAN TO RESUME
MEDITATING TONIGHT.
TOLARIS:
YOU CAN'T GIVE UP AFTER ONE TRY.
T'POL: IT WAS A MISTAKE TO TRY
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
TOLARIS: WASN'T THERE
ANYTHING ENJOYABLE
ABOUT THE EXPERIENCE?
T'POL: I'M READING OVER
20 MILLION CUBIC METERS
OF DISODIUM,
AS WELL AS TRACES
OF ETHYLCHLORATE.
TOLARIS:
WE CAN RUN THE SCANS LATER.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR DREAMS.
YOUR EMOTIONS WERE CLOSER
TO THE SURFACE.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN INTENSE.
T'POL: IT INVOLVED A MEMORY.
I WAS WALKING DOWN A STREET
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
ON EARTH.
TOLARIS:
WHY DID YOU LEAVE THE COMPOUND?
T'POL: I WAS CURIOUS
ABOUT HUMAN RECREATION.
I WANTED TO SEE IT FOR MYSELF.
TOLARIS:
SO YOU BROKE PROTOCOL?
T'POL: IT WAS LATE.
EVERYONE IN THE COMPOUND
HAD GONE TO SLEEP.
I DIDN'T SEE ANY HARM IN LEAVING
FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS.
TOLARIS: WHERE DID YOU GO?
T'POL: I SIMPLY WALKED.
THEN I HEARD MUSIC.
TOLARIS: MUSIC?
T'POL:
IT WAS UNUSUAL, CHAOTIC,
BUT I WAS DRAWN TO IT.
TOLARIS: GO ON.
T'POL: I WENT INTO A RESTAURANT
WHERE MUSICIANS WERE PLAYING.
I SAT AT A TABLE.
TOLARIS: HOW DID YOU FEEL?
T'POL: I CAN'T REMEMBER.
TOLARIS: TRY.
T'POL: I FELT...
INVIGORATED.
TOLARIS: EMOTION.
YOU FELT EMOTION.
T'POL: BRIEFLY.
THEY FINISHED PLAYING,
AND I RETURNED TO THE COMPOUND.
TOLARIS: YOU COULD FEEL
THAT WAY AGAIN, T'POL.
IT ISN'T DIFFICULT, AND IT'S
NOTHING TO BE AFRAID OF.
I CAN SHOW YOU HOW.
TUCKER:
YOU WANT ME TO TALK TO HIM?
ARCHER: FROM WHAT I HEAR,
YOU'VE BECOME FAST FRIENDS.
MAYBE YOU'LL HAVE
BETTER LUCK THAN I DID.
TUCKER: WELL, I'LL TRY,
BUT SOMETHING TELLS ME
IT WON'T BE AS SIMPLE
AS FIXING AN ENGINE.
HE'S GOT A LOT OF RESENTMENT.
ARCHER: DO YOUR BEST.
TUCKER: AYE, SIR.
ARCHER:
WHAT ABOUT THIS TOLARIS FELLOW?
TUCKER: WELL, I HAVEN'T REALLY
GOTTEN TO KNOW HIM.
HE SEEMS KIND OF QUIET, THOUGH.
A LITTLE SULLEN.
ARCHER: T'POL'S BEEN SPENDING
A LOT OF TIME WITH HIM LATELY.
TUCKER: IS THAT A PROBLEM?
ARCHER: TWO DAYS AGO,
SHE COULDN'T WAIT TO GET
THESE PEOPLE OFF THE SHIP.
I PRACTICALLY HAD
TO ORDER HER TO WORK WITH HIM.
NOW THEY'RE ALMOST
INSEPARABLE.
TUCKER: IF I DIDN'T KNOW BETTER,
I'D SAY YOU WERE
A LITTLE JEALOUS.
IF I WAS THE ONLY HUMAN
ON A SHIP FULL OF VULCANS
AND WE RAN INTO AN EARTH VESSEL,
I'D BE SPENDING AS MUCH TIME
WITH THEM AS I COULD.
SHE LIKES BEING AROUND
HER OWN KIND.
WHO DOESN'T?
ARCHER: WELL, LET ME KNOW
HOW IT GOES WITH KOV.
TUCKER: YES, SIR.
T'POL: "MIND-MELD"?
TOLARIS:
IT'S AN ANCIENT TECHNIQUE.
IT WAS ABANDONED CENTURIES AGO.
BUT WE'VE DISCOVERED THAT IT
CAN HELP US ACCESS OUR EMOTIONS.
T'POL: HOW DOES IT WORK?
TOLARIS: I'D BEGIN
BY CREATING A TELEPATHIC LINK.
AND WE WOULD BE ABLE TO SHARE
OUR--OUR MEMORIES, THOUGHTS.
IN ESSENCE,
WE WOULD BECOME ONE MIND.
IT'S QUITE AN EXPERIENCE, BUT...
IT IS PROFOUNDLY INTIMATE.
ARE YOU PREPARED FOR THAT?
IF YOU'D LIKE, WE COULD TRY
A MORE TRADITIONAL FORM
OF GUIDED MEDITATION,
BUT IT WOULDN'T BE
NEARLY AS EFFECTIVE.
T'POL: PROCEED.
TOLARIS: IT'S ALL RIGHT.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
TRY TO FOCUS ON MY VOICE.
MY MIND TO YOUR MIND.
YOUR THOUGHTS TO MY THOUGHTS.
OUR MINDS ARE MERGING.
OUR MINDS
ARE BECOMING ONE.
T'POL: IT'S NOT WORKING.
TOLARIS: YOU'RE RESISTING.
RELAX.
MY MIND TO YOUR MIND.
YOUR THOUGHTS TO MY THOUGHTS.
OUR MINDS ARE MERGING.
OUR MINDS ARE BECOMING ONE.
[TOLARIS SHUDDERS]
[T'POL GASPS]
TOLARIS: AM I WITH YOU?
T'POL: YES.
TOLARIS:
CAN YOU SENSE MY THOUGHTS?
T'POL: YES.
TOLARIS: YOU'RE DOING WELL.
I WANT YOU TO THINK ABOUT
THAT NIGHT
WHEN YOU LEFT THE COMPOUND.
IMAGINE YOURSELF
WALKING DOWN THAT STREET.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION,
LAUGHTER]
GOOD.
NOW LISTEN.
CAN YOU HEAR THE MUSIC?
LISTEN.
[JAZZ PLAYING SOFTLY]
NOW FOLLOW IT.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
I CAN SEE WHY YOU WERE
DRAWN TO THIS PLACE.
IT'S UNLIKE ANYTHING ON VULCAN.
I'M NOT SURPRISED IT TRIGGERED
AN EMOTIONAL RESPONSE.
YOU SAID YOU WERE INVIGORATED.
WHAT ELSE?
T'POL: I DON'T KNOW.
TOLARIS: YES, YOU DO.
YOU'RE JUST NOT USED TO
DESCRIBING YOUR EMOTIONS.
YOU EXPERIENCED OTHER THINGS.
EXCITEMENT ABOUT
BREAKING PROTOCOL,
APPREHENSION ABOUT
GETTING CAUGHT,
AND THE MUSIC--
THE MUSIC MADE YOU FEEL...
ELATED.
ALLOW YOURSELF TO FEEL
THESE EMOTIONS AGAIN.
DON'T HOLD THEM BACK.
T'POL: I HAVE TO RETURN
TO THE COMPOUND.
TOLARIS: YOU'RE ANXIOUS.
IT'S JUST ANOTHER EMOTION.
T'POL: LET ME GO.
TOLARIS: STAY WITH ME, T'POL.
T'POL: NO!
STOP.
TOLARIS: NO.
T'POL: STOP!
THIS WAS A MISTAKE.
TOLARIS: YOU'VE MADE PROGRESS.
DON'T GIVE UP NOW.
T'POL: PLEASE GO.
TOLARIS: T'POL...
T'POL: LEAVE!
TOLARIS: YOU'RE FEELING ANGER.
YOUR EMOTIONS
ARE BREAKING THE SURFACE.
EMBRACE THEM!
WHAT A SHAME.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[T'POL GASPS SOFTLY]
T'POL: T'POL TO SICK BAY.
KOV: I'VE ALREADY BEEN THROUGH
THIS WITH YOUR CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE
MAKING THE RIGHT DECISION?
KOV: IF YOU KNEW MY FATHER,
YOU'D UNDERSTAND.
TUCKER: I DON'T MEAN TO PUT
TOO FINE A POINT ON THIS,
BUT YOU'VE GOT A LIMITED WINDOW
OF OPPORTUNITY.
ONCE IT CLOSES--
KOV:
I CONSIDER YOU A FRIEND, TRIP,
AND I APPRECIATE
WHAT YOU'RE TRYING TO DO,
BUT PLEASE DON'T.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF CONTACTING HIM.
I TEST-FIRED OUR PORT THRUSTER
LAST NIGHT.
IT'S STILL OFF BY 12%.
TUCKER:
OH, PROBABLY A FAULTY INJECTOR.
SHOULD BE EASY ENOUGH TO FIX.
DO VULCANS DANCE?
YOU KNOW...
KOV: OH. ONLY WHEN IT'S PART
OF SOME TEDIOUS CEREMONY.
TUCKER: HMM.
I REMEMBER THE FIRST DANCE
I EVER WENT TO.
BAYSHORE ELEMENTARY,
PANAMA CITY, FLORIDA.
A GIRL I HAD A CRUSH ON,
MELISSA LYLES,
WAS GONNA BE THERE.
SO I SPENT WEEKS PRACTICING
THE TWO-STEP
WITH MY BROTHER.
I WANTED TO
MAKE SURE I WAS READY.
SHE WAS WEARING A RED DRESS
THAT NIGHT.
PRETTIEST GIRL THERE.
ALL I WANTED TO DO
WAS ASK HER TO DANCE WITH ME.
BUT I NEVER WORKED UP
THE COURAGE
TO GO OVER AND TALK TO HER.
I CAUGHT HER LOOKING
AT ME A COUPLE TIMES,
BUT...
I ENDED UP JUST STANDING
IN A CORNER WITH MY BUDDIES.
KOV: INTERESTING.
BUT WHAT DOES THAT HAVE
TO DO WITH OUR THRUSTER PROBLEM?
TUCKER:
IT'S BEEN MORE THAN 20 YEARS
AND I'M STILL KICKING MYSELF
FOR NOT ASKING THAT GIRL
TO DANCE.
YOU PROBABLY DON'T
KNOW THIS, BUT...
REGRET IS ONE OF
THE STRONGEST EMOTIONS.
AND ONE OF THE SADDEST.
I HAVE A FEELING YOU HAVEN'T
HAD A BRUSH WITH IT YET.
BUT IT SOUNDS TO ME LIKE
YOU'RE PRETTY CLOSE.
IT'S SOMETHING
YOU MIGHT WANT TO AVOID.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
TOLARIS: GOOD MORNING.
ARCHER: GOOD MORNING.
CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING?
COFFEE?
TOLARIS: NO, THANKS.
ARCHER: HAVE A SEAT.
TRIP TELLS ME THE REPAIRS
TO YOUR SHIP
ARE ALMOST FINISHED.
YOU SHOULD BE ON YOUR WAY
PRETTY SOON.
TOLARIS: YES.
ARCHER:
HOW'S THAT SURVEY COMING ALONG?
TOLARIS:
WE'LL BE DONE THIS AFTERNOON.
ARCHER: THAT'S GREAT NEWS.
I WANTED TO THANK YOU
FOR ALL OF YOUR HELP.
TOLARIS:
IT WAS THE LEAST WE COULD DO.
BESIDES, WE'VE ENJOYED
SPENDING OUR TIME HERE.
YOU HAVE AN EXCEPTIONAL CREW,
CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: STARFLEET'S FINEST.
SLEEP WELL LAST NIGHT?
TOLARIS: WELL ENOUGH. YOU?
ARCHER: TOSSED AND TURNED.
ALWAYS HAPPENS WHENEVER
WE'RE EXPLORING SOMEPLACE NEW.
TOLARIS: I UNDERSTAND.
WELL, IF THERE'S NOTHING MORE,
CAPTAIN,
I'M EAGER TO GET BACK TO WORK.
WE HAVE ANOTHER 20 MILLION
CUBIC KILOMETERS TO CHART.
ARCHER: SORRY TO KEEP YOU.
I'M AFRAID YOU'LL
BE WORKING ALONE TODAY.
TOLARIS: OH?
ARCHER: SUB-COMMANDER T'POL'S
IN SICK BAY.
FROM WHAT THE DOCTOR TELLS ME,
SHE'S IN PRETTY BAD SHAPE.
TOLARIS: THAT'S UNFORTUNATE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
ARCHER: YOU KNOW DAMN WELL
WHAT HAPPENED.
SHE TOLD ME ABOUT YOUR--
WHAT DID SHE CALL IT?--
MIND-MELD.
SHE SAID WHEN SHE ASKED YOU
TO STOP, YOU GOT ANGRY.
SHE SAID SHE HAD TO
FORCE YOU AWAY.
TOLARIS: WHAT HAPPENED BETWEEN
US IS PERSONAL.
IT'S NOT YOUR CONCERN.
ARCHER: YOU ASSAULTED
A MEMBER OF MY CREW.
TOLARIS: I DID NO SUCH THING.
MIND-MELDS CAN BE
EMOTIONALLY TURBULENT.
SHE SIMPLY PANICKED.
ARCHER: PANIC DOESN'T LAND YOU
IN SICK BAY.
OUR DOCTOR SAID
SHE COULD HAVE SUFFERED
NEUROLOGICAL DAMAGE
THANKS TO YOU.
TOLARIS: NO ONE FORCED HER
TO TRY THE MELD.
SHE DID IT WILLINGLY.
ARCHER:
YOU'VE BEEN MANIPULATING HER
EVER SINCE YOU CAME ABOARD.
TOLARIS: I AM HELPING HER SHED
A LIFETIME OF REPRESSION.
AND YOU, OF ALL PEOPLE,
SHOULD UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TRYING TO DO.
YOU'RE HUMAN.
I NEED TO GO SEE HER.
ARCHER: T'POL'S
HAD ENOUGH OF YOUR HELP.
STAY AWAY FROM HER.
TOLARIS: SHE IS IN A CRUCIAL
STAGE OF HER AWAKENING.
SHE NEEDS GUIDANCE.
I TOLD YOU, IT'S OVER.
TOLARIS: I THINK THAT'S FOR HER
TO DECIDE.
ARCHER: MAYBE I'M NOT
MAKING MYSELF CLEAR.
SICK BAY'S OFF-LIMITS.
TOLARIS: YOU'RE
IN MY WAY, CAPTAIN.
YOU'D BE WISE TO LET ME LEAVE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S WRONG, TOLARIS?
GETTING ANGRY?
I THOUGHT YOU HAD THAT
UNDER CONTROL.
TOLARIS: MOVE ASIDE.
ARCHER: T'POL'S RIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT A TEMPER.
TOLARIS: NOW.
ARCHER: GO TO HELL.
TOLARIS: YOU PLANNED THIS.
ARCHER: IF I'D KNOWN
I WAS GONNA GET THROWN
ACROSS THE ROOM THAT HARD,
I MIGHT HAVE TRIED
A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
I THINK IT'S TIME YOU
AND YOUR FRIENDS
WENT ON YOUR MERRY WAY.
TUCKER: KEEP AN EYE
ON THE INTERMIX PRESSURE.
DON'T LET IT DRIFT ABOVE 5,000.
KOV: 5,000.
TUCKER: AND WATCH
THOSE INJECTOR PORTS.
KOV: I WILL.
I THOUGHT YOU'D LIKE TO KNOW,
I GOT AN UPDATE ON MY FATHER.
APPARENTLY,
HIS CONDITION'S IMPROVED.
TUCKER: IS THAT SO?
KOV: THE SURGEONS IMPLANTED
A VASO-STIMULATOR.
THEY SAY, WITH ANY LUCK,
IT'LL EXTEND HIS LIFE
A FEW YEARS.
TUCKER: I'M GLAD TO HEAR IT.
THAT'LL GIVE YOU
A LITTLE MORE TIME
TO THINK ABOUT
MAKING THAT CALL.
KOV: I ALREADY DID.
MY FATHER'S THE ONE
WHO GAVE ME THE GOOD NEWS.
THANK YOU, TRIP.
TUCKER: ANYTIME.
[DOOR CHIMES]
T'POL: COME IN.
ARCHER: IS THIS A BAD TIME?
T'POL: NOT AT ALL.
ARCHER: FEELING ANY BETTER?
T'POL:
HAS THE VULCAN SHIP LEFT?
ARCHER: ABOUT 20 MINUTES AGO.
T'POL:
THEN, YES, I'M FEELING BETTER.
ARCHER:
YOU DO THIS EVERY NIGHT?
T'POL: EVERY NIGHT.
ARCHER: I THINK
I FINALLY UNDERSTAND WHY.
I'LL SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
DO YOU DREAM?
ARCHER: SURE.
SOMETIMES THEY'RE EVEN IN COLOR.
T'POL: IS IT ENJOYABLE?
ARCHER: MOST NIGHTS.
T'POL: I ENVY YOU.
GOOD NIGHT.
[DOOR CLOSES]