WE COULDN'T DO THIS
IN MY READY ROOM?
TUCKER: OH, THE CAPTAIN'S GOT TO
BE IN THE CAPTAIN'S CHAIR.
TILT YOUR CHIN UP.
ARCHER: JUST TAKE THE PICTURE.
TUCKER: YOU'VE GOT A STANCHION
GROWING OUT OF YOUR HEAD.
SWIVEL TO THE RIGHT
ABOUT 10 DEGREES.
EVERY RECRUIT WALKING
INTO STARFLEET COMMAND
IS GONNA SEE THIS ON THE WALL.
MAYWEATHER:
IT'S A REAL HONOR, SIR.
SEEING THOSE STARFLEET CAPTAINS
EVERY DAY
GAVE US SOMETHING TO ASPIRE TO.
TUCKER: AH, THERE'S A REFLECTION
FROM THAT STATUS DISPLAY.
COULD YOU KILL THE MONITORS
IN THE SITUATION ROOM?
COME ON, T'POL.
THE ARTIST IN OAKLAND NEEDS
A GOOD PICTURE TO PAINT FROM.
ARCHER: DO VULCAN CAPTAINS
HAVE THEIR PORTRAITS
HANGING AT THE HIGH COMMAND?
VULCANS ARE REVERED
FOR THEIR ACCOMPLISHMENTS,
NOT FOR THE WAY THEY LOOK.
TUCKER: EXCEPT FOR THE REALLY
IMPORTANT ONES,
WHO GET MUMMIFIED.
ARCHER: WHY CAN'T THEY JUST USE
A PHOTO FROM MY FILE?
[ CONSOLE BEEPS ]
REED: SIR?
I'M PICKING UP A SMALL PLANET
ON OUR CURRENT HEADING.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT THERE WEREN'T
ANY SYSTEMS ALONG THIS COURSE.
IT'S NOT A SYSTEM, CAPTAIN.
IT'S JUST A PLANET.
ARCHER: PUT IT UP.
ARCHER: MAGNIFY.
T'POL: IT'S A ROGUE.
A PLANET THAT'S BROKEN
OUT OF ITS ORBIT.
ARCHER: LAY IN A COURSE.
-LET'S TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
-AYE, SIR.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
CAPTAIN ARCHER IN COMMAND.
ARCHER: GIVE IT A REST, TRIP.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
T'POL: THIS PLANET SUPPORTS
A DIVERSE ANIMAL POPULATION.
HOSHI: HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
ARCHER: SHOULDN'T THE SURFACE
BE FROZEN SOLID?
T'POL: HOT GAS IS VENTING
FROM THE PLANET'S INTERIOR.
MOST OF THE LIFE FORMS ARE
CONCENTRATED IN THOSE AREAS.
ARCHER: OASES.
ANY PEOPLE?
T'POL: NO EVIDENCE
OF HUMANOID LIFE.
WE'RE PICKING UP A POWER
SIGNATURE NEAR THE EQUATOR.
THERE'S A SHIP DOWN THERE.
ARCHER: TRY TO HAIL THEM.
HOSHI: NO RESPONSE.
TUCKER: MAYBE THEY WANT
TO BE LEFT ALONE.
A SINGLE SHIP ON A DARK PLANET?
MAYBE THEY'RE
ON THEIR HONEYMOON.
[ BEEPING ]
REED: THE INFRARED'S USELESS.
THERE'S TOO MUCH HEAT COMING
FROM THOSE THERMAL VENTS.
ARCHER: WE SHOULD BE
RIGHT OVER THAT SHIP.
I'M SCANNING FOR A BREAK
IN THE CANOPY.
HOSHI: IF THIS IS ANYTHING
LIKE THE AMAZON, GOOD LUCK.
ARCHER: I USED TO SAY
I COULD LAND A SHUTTLEPOD
WITH MY EYES CLOSED.
WELL, THE PROOF'S
IN THE PUDDING, CAPTAIN.
[ BEEPING ]
THERE'S A CLEARING AHEAD,
900 METERS,
BUT IT'S NOT MUCH BIGGER
THAN THE SHUTTLEPOD.
ARCHER: IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE.
[ BEEPING ]
T'POL: CAPTAIN?
THEIR VESSEL IS THAT WAY,
600 METERS.
REED: FOLLOW ME.
ARCHER: WHY DON'T YOU LET ME
PLAY CAPTAIN FOR A WHILE,
MALCOLM?
THIS REMINDS ME OF
THE RAINFOREST IN NEW ZEALAND.
I EARNED MY WILDERNESS
MERIT BADGE THERE.
REED: YOU WERE A BOY SCOUT, SIR?
ARCHER: I WAS AN EAGLE SCOUT.
REED: OH. SO WAS I.
ARCHER: REALLY?
HOW MANY MERIT BADGES?
REED: 28. YOU?
ARCHER: 26.
REED: OH. THAT'S NOT BAD, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
T'POL: CAPTAIN?
WE SPOT ANY MORE CREATURES
LIKE THAT
AND WE'LL EARN
OUR EXOBIOLOGY BADGES.
REED: ACTUALLY...
I ALREADY HAVE THAT ONE.
HOSHI: A CAMPSITE, SIR.
ARCHER: ANYONE HOME?
WE'RE FROM
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
IS THERE ANYONE HERE?
T'POL: I'M STILL NOT DETECTING
ANY BIO-SIGNS,
BUT THEIR SHIP'S LESS THAN
200 METERS IN THAT DIRECTION.
ARCHER: YOU AND MALCOLM
CHECK IT OUT.
WE'LL STAY HERE
IN CASE ANYONE SHOWS UP.
[ TWIG CRACKS ]
Reed: Did you hear that?
T'POL: YES.
REED: ANYTHING?
T'POL: FOR A MOMENT,
I HAD A HUMANOID BIO-SIGN.
IT'S GONE.
[ TWIG CRACKS ]
REED: IT'S NOT GONE.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
REED: CAPTAIN, YOU ALL RIGHT?
ARCHER: EVERYTHING'S FINE.
HUMANOID: THESE ARE THE ESKA.
MY NAME IS DAMRUS.
ARCHER: THIS IS T'POL,
MY SCIENCE OFFICER,
AND LIEUTENANT MALCOLM REED.
REED: PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
YOUR FRIENDS NEARLY SHOT ME
BACK THERE.
ESKAN: WE'RE SORRY.
THERE ARE DANGEROUS ANIMALS
IN THE FOREST.
WE'VE NEVER SEEN OTHER HUMANOIDS
HERE BEFORE.
T'POL: HAVE WE TRESPASSED
IN YOUR TERRITORY?
THIS PLANET
IS NO ONE'S TERRITORY,
BUT IT'S A SPECIAL PLACE FOR US.
ESKAN: WHAT ARE YOU DOING
ON DAKALA?
ARCHER: WE'RE JUST HERE
TO EXPLORE.
WE'D LIKE TO STAY FOR A WHILE,
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT?
IT'S A BIG PLANET.
WE COULD FIND
ANOTHER LANDING SITE,
BUT I WAS HOPING
YOU MIGHT ENJOY THE COMPANY.
YOU AREN'T EXACTLY ROUGHING IT.
DAMRUS: DRAYJIN MEAT IS ONE
OF LIFE'S GREAT PLEASURES.
REED: MMM!
NO ARGUMENT HERE.
I'M CURIOUS WHY OUR SENSORS
DIDN'T DETECT YOU.
DAMRUS: WE USE SENSING CLOAKS.
THEY KEEP THE WILDLIFE
FROM SPOTTING US.
HOSHI: ARE YOU STUDYING
THE WILDLIFE HERE?
[ CHUCKLES ]
ESKAN: NOT EXACTLY.
DAMRUS: WE'RE ON AN,
UH, EXPEDITION.
THAT DRAYJIN YOU'RE EATING--
WE KILLED IT YESTERDAY.
YOU'RE HUNTERS.
DAMRUS: OUR PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR NINE GENERATIONS.
TO KILL THE INDIGENOUS SPECIES?
DAMRUS: TAKING WILD ANIMALS
IS PART OF OUR TRADITION.
THERE ARE HIGHER PRIMATES HERE.
WE DON'T TOUCH THEM.
ARCHER: HUNTING WENT
OUT OF STYLE ON EARTH
OVER A HUNDRED YEARS AGO.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN WE DON'T
APPRECIATE YOUR HOSPITALITY.
REED: THAT GEAR YOU CARRY...
SEEMS PRETTY ELABORATE
TO TAKE DOWN A FEW GAME ANIMALS.
DON'T UNDERESTIMATE
THE GAME ON THIS PLANET.
THEY OFTEN GET THE BETTER OF US.
[ LAUGHING ]
I WONDER IF I MIGHT JOIN
ONE OF YOUR HUNTS.
DAMRUS: I THOUGHT YOUR PEOPLE
DIDN'T APPROVE.
REED: YOU WERE ABLE
TO SNEAK UP ON US
WITHOUT BEING DETECTED
BY OUR NIGHT-VISION SENSORS.
I'D LIKE TO SEE
HOW YOU DID THAT.
I PROMISE
I WON'T KILL ANYTHING, SIR.
[ LAUGHING ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
IT'S, UH, UP TO OUR HOSTS.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
TRIP AND MALCOLM ARE BRINGING
HOSHI BACK TO ENTERPRISE
AND PUTTING TOGETHER
SOME CAMPING GEAR
TO BRING BACK TO THE SURFACE.
IF THE BUGS GLOW IN THE DARK,
AT LEAST YOU CAN TELL
WHEN THEY'VE CRAWLED
INTO YOUR SLEEPING BAG.
HOSHI: ONE MORE REASON I AM
HAPPY TO SPEND THE NIGHT
IN MY OWN BUNK.
ANYWAY, IT'S THE THINGS
YOU CAN'T SEE
THAT I'D BE WORRIED ABOUT.
REED: LIKE THOSE BORE WORMS.
TUCKER: BORE WORMS?
HOSHI: APPARENTLY, THEY CRAWL
INTO YOUR EAR TO LAY THEIR EGGS.
HAVE A NICE NIGHT.
[ REED CHUCKLES ]
T'POL: WE CAN START
WITH THE ENTOMOLOGISTS,
THEN BRING THE OTHER
BIO-SCIENCE TEAMS DOWN.
I'D RECOMMEND WE LIMIT
THE NUMBER OF CREWMEN
ON THE SURFACE TO SIX AT A TIME.
ARCHER: SENSIBLE.
DAMRUS: ENJOYING YOURSELVES?
ARCHER: VERY MUCH.
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR CAMP
WITH US.
DAMRUS: WE'RE HEADING OUT
IN SIX HOURS.
I SUGGEST YOU GET SOME SLEEP
IF YOU'RE STILL PLANNING
TO COME ALONG.
REED: I WOULDN'T MISS IT.
DAMRUS: GOOD NIGHT.
ARCHER: GOOD NIGHT.
REED: NIGHT.
OHH.
I SUPPOSE I'LL TURN IN, THEN.
TUCKER: SOUNDS LIKE A GOOD IDEA.
I THINK I'LL SIT UP FOR A WHILE.
TUCKER: HAVE FUN.
YEAH.
WOMAN: JONATHAN?
JONATHAN?
HELLO?
[ LEAVES RUSTLING ]
IS SOMEONE THERE?
WOMAN: JONATHAN?
WHO'S THERE?
IF THE CAPTAIN SAYS HE SAW HER,
HE SAW HER.
ARCHER: ARE THERE ANY OTHERS
IN YOUR HUNTING PARTY?
ESKAN: NO.
DAMRUS: CERTAINLY NO
HUMAN FEMALES.
YOU SURE SHE WASN'T
FROM YOUR VESSEL?
ARCHER: I'M SURE.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
Mayweather: Mayweather here,
Captain.
There are no other ships
on the surface or in orbit.
THANKS, TRAVIS.
ARCHER OUT.
NOTHING.
ARCHER: SHE WAS YOUNG...
LONG, BLOND HAIR.
SHE WAS WEARING
SOME...KIND OF A NIGHTGOWN.
REED: A NIGHTGOWN, SIR?
T'POL: PERHAPS
YOU WERE DREAMING.
ARCHER: IT WASN'T A DREAM.
SHE SAID MY NAME.
SHE KNEW WHO I WAS.
AND...
I THINK I KNEW HER.
SIR?
THERE WAS SOMETHING ABOUT HER.
I...
I'VE SEEN HER BEFORE.
ON THIS PLANET,
IT'S ALWAYS NIGHT.
YOU'RE SURROUNDED BY THINGS
YOU CAN HEAR BUT NOT SEE.
IT CAN, UH...
STIMULATE THE IMAGINATION.
ESKAN: YOU WOULDN'T BE
THE FIRST PERSON
WHO LOOKED INTO THE JUNGLE
AND SAW SOMETHING
THAT WASN'T THERE.
SHE WAS REAL.
DAMRUS: CAPTAIN ARCHER,
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
YOU'D ENCOUNTER A HALF-NAKED
WOMAN WHO YOU THINK YOU KNOW
DOZENS OF LIGHT YEARS
FROM YOUR HOMEWORLD?
GO TO SLEEP.
IF YOU'RE LUCKY, MAYBE SHE'LL
VISIT YOU IN YOUR DREAMS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
REED: THESE CAN DETECT INFRARED.
DAMRUS: AMONG OTHER THINGS.
TUCKER: WHAT ARE YOU
GOING AFTER TODAY?
ESKAN: WE SAW A PACK
OF FIRE WOLVES YESTERDAY
ABOUT SIX KILOMETERS FROM HERE.
IT'S A DIFFICULT HIKE.
REED: I'LL TRY TO KEEP UP.
[ ESKAN LAUGHS ]
DAMRUS: WE'D APPRECIATE IT.
WE ONLY HAVE TWO DAYS LEFT.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE HURRY?
DAMRUS: TO PRESERVE DAKALA,
OUR LAW STATES
THAT WE'RE ALLOWED TO HUNT HERE
FOR FOUR DAYS EACH YEAR,
THEN WE HAVE TO LEAVE.
ESKAN: HUNTERS OFTEN WAIT
DECADES FOR A CHANCE
TO COME HERE.
T'POL: ARE THOSE VOLCANIC VENTS?
DAMRUS: YES. THAT AREA'S
PARTICULARLY ACTIVE.
MINERAL SPRINGS, STEAM VENTS--
IT'S QUITE SPECTACULAR.
ARCHER: COULD BE WORTH
CHECKING OUT
WHILE MALCOLM'S ON HIS SAFARI.
TUCKER: I'LL GET MY CAMERA.
DAMRUS: DID YOU SLEEP WELL,
CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: YES, FINE.
DAMRUS: GOOD.
IF YOU SEE ANY
BEAUTIFUL FEMALES TODAY,
YOU'LL BE SURE TO LET US KNOW.
[ CHUCKLES ]
DAMRUS: DRAYJIN, A FEMALE.
THEY'RE VERY UNPREDICTABLE.
REMINDS ME OF YELLOWSTONE.
T'POL: IT'S MORE LIKE
THE GROTTOES OF DENEVA PRIME.
I'M DETECTING
A LARGE GEOTHERMAL SHAFT
60 METERS IN THAT DIRECTION.
I'D LIKE TO EXAMINE IT.
SIR?
ARCHER: PERMISSION GRANTED.
STAY IN CONTACT.
TUCKER: SO...
SHE WAS WEARING A NIGHTGOWN?
YOU THINK SHE'S REAL?
ARCHER: I WASN'T HALLUCINATING.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN, IT DOESN'T
MAKE ANY SENSE.
ARCHER: I KNOW.
TRIP...HAVE YOU EVER KNOWN ME
TO DO ANYTHING FOOLISH?
I MEAN, REALLY FOOLISH?
I REMEMBER A POKER GAME
AT JUPITER STATION ONCE.
OTHER THAN THAT...
LAST NIGHT, I WALKED INTO
AN ALIEN JUNGLE, ALONE...
CHASING A WOMAN WHO COULDN'T
POSSIBLY HAVE BEEN THERE.
THAT MIGHT QUALIFY.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
ARCHER: IT WAS LIKE
I WAS BEING DRAWN TO HER,
LIKE I DIDN'T HAVE ANY CONTROL
OVER WHAT I WAS DOING.
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
SHE MUST HAVE BEEN SOME WOMAN.
[ LEAVES RUSTLING ]
[ GROWLING ]
WRAITH!
REED: WHAT IS IT?
IS THERE SOMETHING OUT THERE?
ESKAN: IT COULD BE
A PLUME OF STEAM.
IT CAN FOOL
OUR THERMAL SCANNERS.
REED: WELL, LET'S FIND OUT.
DAMRUS: NO POINT IN ALL OF US
CHASING A SENSOR GHOST.
YOU TWO STAY ON THE TRAIL.
-DAMRUS.
-TAKE CARE OF OUR GUEST.
WE'LL CATCH UP.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
[ PANTING ]
WOMAN: JONATHAN?
ARCHER: WHO ARE YOU?
[ BEEPING ]
HOW DO YOU KNOW MY NAME?
I...NEED YOU, JONATHAN.
YOU'RE SPEAKING ENGLISH.
I NEED YOU TO UNDERSTAND.
I KNOW YOU.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
IF YOU DIDN'T KNOW ME,
WOULD YOU HAVE COME?
YOU SAID YOU NEEDED ME.
WHY?
YOU'RE DIFFERENT.
DIFFERENT?
WHAT IS IT?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
HARM.
I DON'T WANT TO HARM YOU.
NOT JONATHAN.
THEN WHO?
WHO WANTS TO HARM YOU?
TUCKER: CAPTAIN?
T'POL: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
FINE.
TUCKER: YOU DISAPPEARED ON US.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING OUT HERE?
JUST...
...TAKING SOME SCANS.
[ SCREECHING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
-HOLD HIM!
-I'M TRYING!
DAMRUS: IF YOU CAN'T
KEEP HIM STEADY...
ESKAN: BURZAAN,
YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE,
BUT YOU HAVE TO BE STILL.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
-WHAT DID THAT?
-I DIDN'T SEE IT.
Hoshi: Go ahead, sir.
WE SPLIT OFF
TO FOLLOW ANOTHER TRAIL.
TELL DR. PHLOX TO STAND BY.
Hoshi: Yes, sir.
DAMRUS: IT WAS A DRAYJIN.
THE FEMALES CAN BE
VERY AGGRESSIVE,
ESPECIALLY IF THEY'RE
PROTECTING A NEST.
ESKAN: THE WOUND'S DEEP.
GET ME THE BONDING KIT!
T'POL: THERE'S NO
INTERNAL DAMAGE,
BUT HE'S LOST A GREAT DEAL
OF BLOOD.
ARCHER: WE'VE GOT A DOCTOR
ON BOARD OUR SHIP.
I'VE ALERTED HIM TO STAND BY.
DAMRUS: WE'RE PREPARED TO DEAL
WITH INJURIES HERE, CAPTAIN.
ESKAN: WE NEED HIM FOR THE HUNT.
IF THEIR DOCTOR CAN HELP...
WE ONLY HAVE TWO MORE DAYS.
DAMRUS: THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
OBVIOUSLY, WE WANT HIM
TO HAVE THE BEST TREATMENT.
ARCHER: LET'S GET HIM BACK
TO THE SHUTTLEPOD.
YOU AND MALCOLM GO WITH HIM.
DAMRUS: YOU SHOULD ALL
RETURN TO YOUR SHIP.
WE CAME TO THIS PLANET
AWARE OF ITS DANGERS.
YOU DIDN'T.
ARCHER: I'M NOT READY TO LEAVE.
T'POL: LIEUTENANT REED REPORTS
THEY'VE DOCKED WITH ENTERPRISE.
ARCHER: THANKS.
T'POL?
COME IN.
I SAW HER AGAIN...
NEAR THE THERMAL VENTS.
SHE SPOKE TO ME.
T'POL: WHAT DID SHE SAY?
ARCHER: SHE SAID SHE...
NEEDED ME.
I THINK...SOMEONE MAY
BE TRYING TO HURT HER.
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD RECONSIDER
RETURNING TO ENTERPRISE.
AND HAVE DR. PHLOX
TAKE A LOOK AT ME?
THERE ARE NO
PSYCHOTROPIC COMPOUNDS HERE.
I WASN'T HALLUCINATING,
AND I WASN'T DREAMING.
SO, THE ONLY LOGICAL CONCLUSION
IS THAT SHE IS
A REAL HUMAN WOMAN?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE IS.
I KNOW IT'S NOT POSSIBLE
FOR HER TO BE HUMAN,
BUT SHE'S APPEARING TO ME
FOR A REASON,
AND I'M GOING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT IT IS.
HOW?
I'M GOING TO FIND HER.
-I'LL GO WITH YOU.
-NO.
A WELL-ARMED HUNTER
WAS NEARLY KILLED TODAY.
IT WOULD BE FOOLISH
TO GO INTO THE JUNGLE ALONE.
I HAVE TO.
SHE'S CHOSEN
TO COMMUNICATE WITH ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHY.
BUT I DON'T THINK
SHE'D REVEAL HERSELF
IF ANYONE ELSE WAS AROUND.
IS THAT YOUR ONLY REASON
FOR GOING BY YOURSELF?
WHAT?
WITH RESPECT, CAPTAIN, I WONDER
IF YOU WOULD BE SO DETERMINED
TO FIND THIS APPARITION
IF IT WERE A SCANTILY CLAD MAN.
TUCKER: HOW'S HE DOING, DOC?
PHLOX: IT WAS A SIMPLE MATTER
TO SYNTHESIZE HIS BLOOD TYPE
FOR A TRANSFUSION.
HE'LL BE BACK ON HIS FEET
IN A FEW HOURS.
TUCKER: I'LL LET
THE CAPTAIN KNOW.
PHLOX: COMMANDER, COULD YOU,
UH, TELL ME WHAT ATTACKED HIM?
TUCKER: THEY CALL IT A DRAYJIN.
IT LOOKS LIKE A BIG, NASTY PIG.
KIND OF TASTES LIKE ONE, TOO.
PHLOX: I FOUND CELLULAR RESIDUE
IN THE WOUND.
IT CLEARLY DOESN'T BELONG
TO THIS GENTLEMAN.
I ASSUME IT MUST HAVE COME
FROM THE ANIMAL THAT MAULED HIM.
TUCKER: WHAT AM I LOOKING AT?
PHLOX: THE CELLS ARE IN A STATE
OF CHROMOSOMAL FLUX.
THEY'RE MUTATING.
IT'S AS IF THEY'RE TRYING
TO CHANGE INTO SOMETHING
BUT CAN'T QUITE FIGURE OUT WHAT.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
A MOST UNUSUAL PIG.
HELLO?
ARE YOU THERE?
[ BEEPING ]
I'M ALONE.
UH!
JONATHAN.
YOU'RE NOT A HALLUCINATION.
YOU'RE REAL.
I CAN TOUCH YOU.
REAL. YES.
BUT...YOU'RE NOT HUMAN, ARE YOU?
HUMAN?
HUMAN...LIKE ME.
WE ARE NOT LIKE YOU.
JONATHAN: "WE"?
THERE ARE MORE OF YOU?
WHERE?
I HAVEN'T SEEN OTHERS.
WOMAN: WE CAN BECOME
WHATEVER YOU SEE--
A TREE, AN ANIMAL, WATER,
WHATEVER YOU SEE.
ARCHER: I SEE A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
BECAUSE YOU WANT TO SEE
A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
HOW DO YOU KNOW WHAT I WANT?
I CAN SEE YOUR THOUGHTS.
I SEE WHAT ELUDES YOU.
YOU'RE TELEPATHIC.
THAT'S HOW YOU KNOW MY LANGUAGE.
I KNOW MORE THAN YOUR LANGUAGE.
THEN YOU MUST KNOW
WHY I'M SO DRAWN TO YOU,
WHY I FEEL LIKE I KNOW YOU.
YOU DO KNOW ME.
FROM WHERE?
WHY DID YOU CHOOSE ME?
YOU'RE DIFFERENT.
YOU SAID THAT BEFORE.
HOW?
WHO AM I DIFFERENT FROM?
THE OTHERS.
THE ONLY ONES WHO HAVE EVER
COME HERE BEFORE YOU.
YOU MEAN THE ESKA.
DO YOU KNOW WHY THEY COME?
TO HUNT.
TO HUNT US, JONATHAN.
WE ARE WHAT THEY PRIZE
ABOVE ALL ELSE.
TUCKER: YOU LOST THE DRAYJIN,
BUT AT LEAST YOU GOT
SOME SCARS TO SHOW FOR IT.
BURZAAN: WELL, THANKS TO YOUR
DOCTOR, I DON'T EVEN HAVE THAT.
DAMRUS: TO THE CAPTAIN
AND HIS FINE PHYSICIAN.
ARCHER: IT WAS NO PROBLEM,
REALLY.
ESKAN: WELL, WE HAVE TO DRINK
TO SOMETHING
SINCE WE CAME BACK EMPTY-HANDED.
[ LAUGHTER ]
TO...
GOOD HUNTING TOMORROW.
-HEAR, HEAR.
-CHEERS.
-TO GOOD HUNTING.
-MM-HMM.
REED: SO, HOW'D YOU LOSE THEM?
DAMRUS: DRAYJIN ARE MIGRATORY.
BY THE TIME WE GOT BACK,
THEY MOVED ON.
ARCHER: ALL THOSE
IMAGING SENSORS,
AND YOU COULDN'T SEE
WHERE THEY WENT?
THEY'RE MORE ELUSIVE
THAN YOU GIVE THEM CREDIT FOR.
TUCKER: APPARENTLY.
DO YOU HUNT ON YOUR OWN WORLD?
YES.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THEN WHY TRAVEL LIGHT YEARS
TO HUNT HERE?
SEEMS LIKE A LONG WAY TO COME
JUST TO SHOOT A FEW WILD PIGS.
WE HUNT MORE THAN WILD PIGS.
THE PREY HERE IS DIFFERENT.
BOAR...
WOLVES, SOME LARGE REPTILES.
IT DOESN'T SEEM THAT DIFFERENT.
DAMRUS: IMAGINE HUNTING
SOMETHING THAT CAN
GET INSIDE YOUR MIND,
SENSE YOUR THOUGHTS.
IS THAT DIFFERENT ENOUGH?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
BURZAAN: WRAITHS.
TUCKER: YOU MEAN GHOSTS?
THEY MIGHT AS WELL BE.
ARCHER: COME ON, FELLAS.
THAT SEEMS PRETTY FARFETCHED.
DOES IT?
YOU SAW ONE YOURSELF.
YOUR MYSTERY WOMAN?
SHE WAS UNDOUBTEDLY A WRAITH
WHO WANDERED TOO CLOSE TO CAMP.
BUT SHE LOOKED HUMAN.
[ LAUGHS ]
BURZAAN: YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF IT WAS A SHE.
ESKAN: THEY'RE SHAPE-SHIFTERS.
THEY CAN LOOK LIKE ANYTHING,
EVEN PEOPLE YOU KNOW.
DAMRUS: THAT'S HOW THEY
TRICK YOU.
T'POL: THEY SOUND LIKE
INTELLIGENT, SENTIENT BEINGS.
DAMRUS: NOT THE WAY YOU OR I
WOULD MEASURE INTELLIGENCE.
IT'S AN INSTINCTUAL RESPONSE.
THAT'S WHY WE WERE TRACKING YOU
THE DAY YOU ARRIVED.
WE THOUGHT THEY'D TAKEN
YOUR FORM.
ESKAN: THEY ASSUME
THE EXACT CHARACTERISTICS
OF WHATEVER THEY BECOME.
THEY TURN INTO A ROCK,
ALL YOU SEE IS A ROCK,
EVEN ON SCANNERS.
DAMRUS: BEFORE WE LEARNED
HOW TO SPOT THEM,
THEY KILLED MORE OF US
THAN WE DID OF THEM.
MY FATHER CAME HERE
WITH EIGHT OTHER HUNTERS.
THEY DROVE A GROUP OF WRAITHS
INTO A BLIND CANYON.
MY FATHER WAS SURE
THAT THEY HAD THEM CUT OFF.
BUT WHEN THEY MOVED IN...
THE WRAITHS WERE WAITING.
THEY'D READ THE HUNTERS' MINDS.
THEY KNEW THEIR PLAN.
MY FATHER MADE IT OUT, BUT ONLY
TWO OF HIS FRIENDS SURVIVED.
[ CHUCKLING ]
HOW DO YOU CATCH THEM?
IN RECENT YEARS, WE--
WE LEARNED WHEN YOU CORNER THEM,
THEY PANIC...
ESPECIALLY THE YOUNG ONES.
DAMRUS: WHEN THEY'RE AFRAID,
THEY EMIT A CHEMICAL SIGNATURE.
OUR SCANNERS HAVE BEEN MODIFIED
TO DETECT IT.
IT GIVES US AN ADVANTAGE.
ARCHER: THEY KNOW DAMN WELL
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
T'POL: I FIND THIS AS
DISTASTEFUL AS YOU DO, CAPTAIN.
I'M JUST NOT SURE
HOW WE CAN STOP THEM.
REED: THEY'RE WELL-ARMED,
AND THEY KNOW THE TERRAIN.
I WOULDN'T WANT TO TRY AND TAKE
THEIR WEAPONS FROM THEM.
T'POL: WE HAVE NO RIGHT TO,
IN ANY CASE.
TUCKER: WHAT RIGHT DO THEY HAVE
TO COME TO THIS PLANET
AND SHOOT THE LOCALS?
ARCHER: HUNTING WILD BOAR
IS ONE THING,
BUT THEY'RE KILLING
A SENTIENT SPECIES.
T'POL: EVEN IF WE STOP THEM,
THEIR PEOPLE WILL CONTINUE
TO COME HERE AND HUNT.
THEY'VE DONE IT
FOR HUNDREDS OF YEARS.
ARCHER: UNLESS WE FIND
A MORE PERMANENT SOLUTION.
PHLOX: CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: THE HUNTERS SAID
THE SHAPE-SHIFTERS
EMIT A CHEMICAL SIGNATURE
WHEN THEY'RE AFRAID.
THAT'S WHAT GIVES THEM AWAY.
YOU HAVE A SAMPLE
OF THEIR CELLS.
PHLOX: I'VE BEEN ANALYZING
THEIR MUTATIVE ABILITY--
QUITE REMARKABLE.
ARCHER: CAN YOU FIND A WAY
TO MASK THAT CHEMICAL?
THAT WOULD SHIELD THEM
FROM THE HUNTERS' SCANS.
PHLOX: I'LL START RIGHT AWAY.
ARCHER: WE MAY NOT BE ABLE TO
STOP THEM FROM HUNTING HERE,
BUT WE COULD LEVEL
THE PLAYING FIELD.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
-EVENING, CAPTAIN.
-TRIP.
GET YOU ANYTHING?
NO, THANKS.
MILK, COLD.
DO YOU KNOW ANY POETRY?
YOU MEAN BESIDES "THERE WAS
A YOUNG LADY FROM IPSWICH"?
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHEN I WAS A KID,
IF I HAD TROUBLE SLEEPING,
MY MOTHER WOULD RECITE
A POEM TO ME.
THERE WAS ONE
I ALWAYS ASKED FOR.
HAD A FUNNY NAME--"THE...SONG
OF THE WANDERING AENGUS."
I DIDN'T LEARN TILL I WAS OLDER
THAT IT WAS BY YEATS.
"I WENT OUT TO THE HAZEL WOOD
BECAUSE A FIRE WAS IN MY HEAD."
ANYWAY...
THE MAN IN THE POEM
CATCHES A FISH,
AND IT TURNS INTO
A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN...
WITH APPLE BLOSSOMS IN HER HAIR.
SHE CALLS HIS NAME
AND THEN VANISHES.
AND?
HE SPENDS THE REST OF HIS LIFE
SEARCHING FOR HER.
HIS...VISION OF PERFECTION,
I SUPPOSE,
SOMETHING HE COULD NEVER
QUITE FIND.
IT'S HER.
CAPTAIN.
WHEN I LISTENED TO THE POEM,
I MUST HAVE CREATED AN IMAGE
OF THAT WOMAN IN MY MIND.
I HAVEN'T THOUGHT ABOUT IT
IN YEARS.
THAT'S WHY I DIDN'T
RECOGNIZE HER AT FIRST.
SHE ISN'T SOMEONE
THAT I EVER KNEW.
SHE'S SOMEONE I IMAGINED
AS A CHILD:
THE ELUSIVE WOMAN FROM THE POEM.
WHY DO YOU THINK
THIS SHAPE-SHIFTER
REACHED INTO YOUR MIND
AND PICKED AN IMAGE
YOU'D ALMOST FORGOTTEN?
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE THAT POEM'S BEEN ON
YOUR MIND MORE THAN YOU REALIZE.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Phlox: Phlox to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: ARCHER.
Phlox: Captain,
I may have found something.
ARCHER: I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
SHE MAY JUST BE SOMETHING
I ENVISIONED A LONG TIME AGO...
BUT I'LL BE DAMNED IF I'M GONNA
LET ANYONE SHOOT HER.
-ARE YOU SURE?
-IT'S A WRAITH.
BURZAAN: I'M NOT PICKING UP
A SIGNATURE.
IT WAS PROBABLY JUST A DRAYJIN.
ESKAN: I SAW IT SHIFT.
IT'S A WRAITH.
DAMRUS: STAY WITH IT.
[ SNARLING ]
BURZAAN: WHERE IS IT?
ESKAN: I'M NOT PICKING UP
ANYTHING.
DAMRUS: IT HAS TO BE HERE.
THERE'S NO WAY OUT.
BURZAAN: WELL, IF IT'S CORNERED,
IT MUST BE TERRIFIED.
WHY CAN'T WE DETECT IT?
DAMRUS: IT MAY NOT BE AFRAID
NOW, BUT IT'S ABOUT TO BE.
[ SCREECHES ]
[ GROANS ]
ESKAN: I'M ALL RIGHT.
DAMRUS: SOMETHING'S WRONG.
WE SHOULD'VE SEEN IT.
BURZAAN: MAYBE OUR SCANNERS
AREN'T WORKING.
DAMRUS: ALL OF THEM?
[ SCREECHING IN DISTANCE ]
BURZAAN: WE NEED TO LEAVE.
DAMRUS: LET'S GET BACK TO CAMP.
[ SCREECHING CONTINUES ]
ARCHER: HOW WAS THE HUNT?
ANY LUCK?
DAMRUS: WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
ARCHER: WE WANTED TO TAKE
A FEW MORE SCANS BEFORE WE LEFT.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
DAMRUS: WE'RE FINE.
TUCKER: YOU SURE?
YOU LOOK PRETTY RATTLED.
BURZAAN: OUR SCANNERS
ARE MALFUNCTIONING.
ARCHER: SORRY TO HEAR IT.
LOOKS LIKE YOU WON'T BE TAKING
HOME ANY TROPHIES THIS YEAR.
STRANGE...
BUT WE NEVER FAILED
ON THE HUNT BEFORE YOU ARRIVED.
ARCHER: I GUESS
WE MUST BE BAD LUCK.
ARE YOU THERE?
WOMAN: YES.
THEY'RE GONE.
WOMAN: FOR NOW.
ARCHER: DID YOU GIVE THE OTHERS
THE MASKING AGENT?
YES.
IT'LL KEEP YOU SAFE.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
YOU REMEMBERED.
THANK YOU...
FOR REMINDING ME.
NEVER STOP SEEKING
WHAT SEEMS UNOBTAINABLE.
GOODBYE, JONATHAN.
DON'T FORGET ME.
I WON'T.