[COMPUTER BEEPS]
[CONVERSATION IN FERENGI]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[CONVERSATIONS IN FERENGI]
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
TUCKER:
DOC, ISN'T MY TIME UP YET?
YOU SAID 20 MINUTES.
IT'S BEEN AT LEAST AN HOUR.
GETTING A LITTLE WELL DONE
IN HERE.
DOCTOR?
HELLO?
[SIGHS]
[SNIFFS]
[CONVERSATION IN FERENGI]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[CREATURE GROWLING]
-AAH!
[SPEAKING FERENGI]
[GRUNTING]
[SNIFFS]
BLECCH!
OOH.
[SNIFFS]
[SIGHS]
[CONVERSATION IN FERENGI]
ARCHER: WHO ARE YOU?
[ALIEN SPEAKS FERENGI]
ARCHER: I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT?
[ALIEN SPEAKS FERENGI]
...WHAT I'M SAYING?
ALIEN 2: SIT DOWN!
ARCHER: UGH!
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
ALIEN: WHO WE ARE
IS UNIMPORTANT.
DO YOU COMMAND THIS SHIP?
I'M THE CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
TO MY CREW?
ALIEN: THEY'RE SLEEPING.
THEY WON'T BE HARMED
AS LONG AS YOU COOPERATE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHERE IS THE LOCATION
OF YOUR VAULT?
VAULT?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
ALIEN: MAYBE THE TRANSLATOR'S
MALFUNCTIONING.
ALIEN 2: HE UNDERSTANDS.
THIS IS A VESSEL OF EXPLORATION,
NOT A CARGO SHIP.
WE DON'T DO ANY COMMERCE.
WHATEVER IT IS YOU'RE AFTER,
YOU WON'T FIND IT HERE.
ALIEN: YOU CARRY NO VALUABLES
OF ANY KIND?
NO PRECIOUS GEMS, NO LATINUM?
I JUST TOLD YOU.
ALIEN: LIAR!
WHOEVER YOU ARE...
JUST TAKE WHAT YOU WANT
AND GET OFF MY SHIP.
ALIEN: COUSIN, MAYBE WE SHOULD.
WE'VE MADE SOME
GOOD ACQUISITIONS ALREADY.
ALIEN 2: THERE'S MORE HERE.
HE'S HIDING SOMETHING.
ALIEN 3: I AGREE WITH KREM.
LET'S TAKE WHAT WE HAVE AND GO.
ALIEN 4: WHAT DO WE HAVE?
SCANNERS, LOW-GRADE WEAPONS.
NOTHING BUT TRINKETS.
KREM: DON'T FORGET
ABOUT THE FEMALES.
SOME OF THEM ARE WORTH
THEIR WEIGHT IN LATINUM.
IF WE LEAVE NOW,
WE COULD MAKE THE NEXT
SLAVE MARKET ON STAMERIS.
SLAVE MARKET?
ALIEN: YOU'RE RIGHT, KREM.
PICK OUT THE FEMALES
THAT WILL BRING THE BEST PRICE.
KREM: I ALREADY HAVE.
IT WAS A PLEASURE DOING
BUSINESS WITH YOU.
WAIT.
YOU'VE RECONSIDERED?
I'LL SHOW YOU
WHERE THE VAULT IS...
IF YOU LET ME KEEP
HALF THE GOLD.
ALIEN: GOLD-PRESSED LATINUM?
GOLD BARS.
HUNDREDS OF THEM.
BUT I KEEP HALF.
ALIEN: 10%.
ARCHER: 40%.
ALIEN: 15%.
ARCHER: 35%
AND NOT A BAR LESS.
YOU'LL NEVER FIND THE VAULT
WITHOUT MY HELP.
ALIEN: 20%--FINAL OFFER.
NO DEAL.
I'D RATHER YOU TAKE
THE WOMEN AND GO.
ALIEN: 35%.
THAT'S NOT A BAD OFFER, ULIS.
MAYBE WE SHOULD CONSIDER IT.
ULIS: NO. WE'LL FIND
THE VAULT OURSELVES.
KREM, START LOADING
THE MERCHANDISE.
KREM: WHY AM I ALWAYS STUCK
DOING THE MENIAL LABOR?
ULIS: MAKE HIM DO IT.
KREM: OH, NOT THERE.
OVER HERE.
ARCHER: IF YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
A HABIT OUT OF THIS,
YOU MIGHT WANT TO GET
A BIGGER SHIP.
KREM: IT'S NOT MY SHIP.
IT'S MY COUSIN'S.
ARCHER: REALLY?
I WAS GETTING THE IMPRESSION
YOU WERE IN CHARGE.
[KREM CHUCKLING]
THIS IS ONLY MY FIRST MONTH
ON THE JOB.
ARCHER: HOW DO YOU
LIKE IT SO FAR?
KREM: MY COUSIN'S
A SKILLFUL MERCHANT.
I'M LEARNING A LOT FROM HIM.
OH, YOU'D BETTER SLIDE THAT OVER
TO MAKE ROOM FOR THE OTHERS.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
KREM: HMM.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU NEED
ALL THIS FOR, ANYWAY?
YOU SEEM TO ALREADY HAVE
PLENTY OF TECHNOLOGY.
KREM: ONE CAN NEVER
HAVE TOO MUCH.
THE RULES OF ACQUISITION
SAY EXPAND OR DIE.
ARCHER: RULES OF ACQUISITION?
KREM: THAT'S RULE NUMBER 45.
I'VE MEMORIZED ALL 173,
INCLUDING THE MOST
IMPORTANT ONE--
A MAN IS ONLY WORTH
THE SUM OF HIS POSSESSIONS.
BACK ON MY HOMEWORLD,
THAT KIND OF THINKING
ALMOST DESTROYED
OUR CIVILIZATION.
KREM: YOU SHOULD HAVE MANAGED
YOUR BUSINESSES BETTER.
COME ON.
WE HAVE A LOT MORE
MOVING TO DO.
WE?
ARCHER: SO, WHAT DO YOU DO,
SPLIT THE PROFITS EQUALLY
BETWEEN THE FOUR OF YOU?
KREM: OH, MY COUSIN
DETERMINES THE SHARES.
ARCHER: YOU MUST GET A BIGGER
PERCENTAGE THAN YOUR CREWMATES.
KREM: ACTUALLY,
I GET THE SMALLEST.
ARCHER: OH, THAT
DOESN'T SEEM FAIR.
YOU'RE THE ONE
DOING ALL THE WORK.
KREM: MY COUSIN KNOWS
WHAT'S BEST FOR ME.
HE MANAGES
ALL MY FINANCIAL TRANSACTIONS.
ARCHER: REALLY?
KREM: I DON'T HAVE
THE LOBES FOR BUSINESS.
ARCHER: I ASSUME HE CHARGES YOU
FOR HIS SERVICES.
KREM: OF COURSE.
HE WOULDN'T BE A VERY GOOD
BUSINESSMAN IF HE DIDN'T.
NEVER ALLOW FAMILY TO STAND
IN THE WAY OF PROFIT.
ARCHER: ANOTHER ONE
OF YOUR RULES?
KREM: NUMBER 6.
ARCHER: AH.
KREM: MY COUSIN'S
GOING TO HELP ME
ACQUIRE MY OWN SHIP SOME DAY.
[ARCHER COUGHING]
YOU THINK YOU COULD BRING ME
A GLASS OF WATER?
[COUGHING]
IT COMES OUT OF A DISPENSER
IN THE MESS HALL.
KREM: I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
OOH, DO YOU THINK
YOU COULD BRING ME
SOME FOOD
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT?
WHATEVER'S LEFT
IN THE SERVING CASE.
THAT IS, IF YOU HAVEN'T
ALREADY TAKEN EVERYTHING.
TUCKER: YOU ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: NEVER BETTER. YOU?
TUCKER: FROM WHAT
I CAN TELL, YOU AND I
ARE THE ONLY ONES ON THE SHIP
STILL STANDING.
I WOULD'VE TRIED TO WAKE
SOME OF THE OTHERS,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING LEFT
IN SICK BAY TO DO IT WITH.
ARCHER: I'M NOT SURPRISED.
THESE ALIENS ARE TAKING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN GET
THEIR HANDS ON.
TUCKER: WHO ARE THEY?
ARCHER: I DON'T KNOW YET.
CAN YOU GET A PHASE PISTOL?
TUCKER: THEY CLEANED OUT
THE ARMORY.
ARCHER: THERE ARE 14
WEAPONS LOCKERS ON THIS SHIP.
THEY CAN'T HAVE EMPTIED
EVERY ONE OF THEM.
TUCKER: TRUST ME, CAPTAIN,
I'VE ALREADY CHECKED.
ARCHER: I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA NEED
SOME HELP TO PULL IT OFF.
THEY USED A HYPOSPRAY
TO WAKE ME UP.
IT'S IN LAUNCH BAY 2.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
KREM: THIS IS PRETTY GOOD.
ARCHER: GLAD YOU'RE ENJOYING IT.
KREM: MAYBE WE SHOULD
TAKE YOUR COOK WITH US.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
ARCHER: DO YOU MIND?
KREM: OH. OH.
OH.
UM...
COMMANDER?
TUCKER: YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
JUST BECAUSE A GUY'S
IN HIS UNDERWEAR,
YOU THINK THE WORST.
T'POL: I ASSUME YOU HAVE
AN EXPLANATION.
TUCKER: DR. PHLOX MADE ME
CLEAR BIO-SCAN
AFTER I GOT BACK
FROM THAT LUNAR SURVEY.
WHILE I WAS IN DECON,
SOMETHING KNOCKED OUT
THE ENTIRE CREW.
ALIENS ARE IN CONTROL
OF THE SHIP.
THAT ARTIFACT YOU BROUGHT
BACK FROM THE LUNAR SURFACE--
IT MUST HAVE BEEN PLACED
THERE INTENTIONALLY.
WHEN I OPENED IT, THE CANISTER
RELEASED SOME KIND OF GAS.
[DOOR OPENING]
KREM: THIS FEMALE...
IS DIFFERENT
FROM THE OTHERS.
WHAT SPECIES IS SHE?
ARCHER: SHE'S A VULCAN.
VULCAN.
THEY'RE REALLY NOT
ALL THAT INTERESTING
ONCE YOU GET TO KNOW THEM.
I'D LIKE TO GET TO KNOW
THIS ONE.
MAYBE I WON'T SELL HER.
NOT RIGHT AWAY.
TRUST ME.
SHE'S GOT NO SENSE OF HUMOR.
ARCHER: SHE'S
ALWAYS COMPLAINING.
[KREM SIGHS]
ARCHER: KREM.
KREM: HUH?
[DOOR OPENS]
YOU OK?
T'POL: THERE ARE TIMES
I WISH VULCANS HADN'T LEARNED
TO REPRESS THEIR
VIOLENT TENDENCIES.
TUCKER: COME ON,
WE GOT WORK TO DO.
T'POL: WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?
TUCKER: I CAN'T WAKE
ANYBODY ELSE UP.
THIS HYPOSPRAY IS EMPTY.
LET'S GO...
UNLESS YOU WANT TO BE
SOLD INTO SLAVERY.
[SIGHS]
ALIEN: THERE'S NOTHING HERE.
ALIEN 2: YOU'RE NOT
SCANNING DEEP ENOUGH.
THIS IS THEIR VAULT.
I SAW ONE JUST LIKE IT
ON A GAVARIAN SHIP.
ALIEN 1: WHY WOULD THEY KEEP
A VAULT IN THE MEDICAL BAY?
ULIS: RULE OF ACQUISITION
NUMBER 23--
NOTHING IS MORE IMPORTANT
THAN YOUR HEALTH...
-EXCEPT FOR YOUR MONEY.
-YOUR MONEY.
ALIEN: I DON'T SEE
A LOCKING MECHANISM.
ALIEN 2: IT MUST USE SOME SORT
OF MAGNETIC SEAL.
I'LL NEED MICROCHARGES
TO BLOW IT OPEN.
HOLD ON.
ALIEN: OH.
ALIEN 2: WHOA. WHOA.
AAH!
ALIEN: THIS IS A WASTE OF TIME.
WE'VE ONLY GOT 3 HOURS
BEFORE THEY BEGIN TO WAKE.
IT'LL TAKE DAYS
TO SEARCH EVERY HATCH.
ULIS: WE'LL FIND IT, MUK.
BE PATIENT. OPEN THOSE.
ALIEN: EMPTY.
MUK: AH! I FOUND SOMETHING!
ULIS: GOLD?
MUK: NO.
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE
QUALITY MERCHANDISE.
OH, SPLENDID CRAFTSMANSHIP.
ULIS: ADD IT TO THE POT.
DO I LOOK LIKE A MENK TO YOU?
THIS BEAUTY'S GOING
IN MY PERSONAL COLLECTION.
ULIS: WE AGREED
TO SPLIT OUR PROFITS.
MUK: YOU SAID THIS SHIP
WOULD MAKE US RICH.
WE'LL BE LUCKY
IF WE BREAK EVEN.
ULIS: WE HAD A DEAL.
MUK: I'M AMENDING IT.
ANYTHING I FIND, I KEEP.
ULIS: FINE. I'LL JUST DEDUCT IT
FROM YOUR SHARE OF THE GOLD.
MUK: WHAT'S WRONG, ULIS?
CAN'T FIND YOUR POT OF GOLD?
ULIS: WHAT'S ALL THIS?
MUK: HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
DON'T TOUCH.
ULIS: IF YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO HELP US,
YOU SHOULD RETURN
TO THE SHIP.
AND WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
LOOKING FOR THE VAULT.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO PUT IT
ON A MAP, YOU IDIOT.
I KNOW THAT.
BUT LOOK.
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN, THESE
ARE THE CAPTAIN'S QUARTERS.
ULIS: SO?
ALIEN: THAT'S WHERE YOU
KEEP YOUR LATINUM.
ULIS: HMM?
WHAT'S THE QUICKEST ROUTE?
ALIEN: WE COULD TAKE
THIS ELEVATOR TO THIS DECK
AND CUT THROUGH HERE.
ULIS: IT'S WORTH A LOOK.
[ALARM]
ULIS: WEAPONS!
WHERE IS IT COMING FROM?
ALIEN: OVER HERE!
[ALIEN GROANING]
ALIEN: MAKE IT STOP!
[ALARM STOPS]
ULIS: LET'S GET TO
THEIR CAPTAIN'S QUARTERS.
[CHUCKLES]
MUK: WHERE ARE MY SCANNERS?
I LEFT THEM RIGHT HERE!
ULIS: YOU SHOULD BE MORE CAREFUL
WITH YOUR ACQUISITIONS.
MUK: OH, OH!
OPEN YOUR BAG.
ULIS: NO.
MUK: OPEN IT.
ULIS: ARE YOU
CALLING ME A THIEF?
MUK: EVERYBODY KNOWS
YOU'D STEAL
THE WAX OUT OF
YOUR OWN MOTHER'S EARS.
ALIEN: PLEASE, GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE PARTNERS.
MUK: PARTNERS DON'T
ROB FROM EACH OTHER.
ULIS: WHY WOULD I BOTHER TAKING
SOME WORTHLESS SCANNERS?
[BEEPING]
MUK: WORTHLESS?
ULIS: I DIDN'T PUT THEM THERE.
MUK: OH, REALLY?
THEN WHO DID?
ULIS: I TELL YOU, I DON'T KNOW!
MUK: MAYBE THEY JUST JUMPED OFF
THE TABLE AND CRAWLED INSIDE.
WHERE'S THE OTHER ONE?
THERE WERE 3.
DON'T LOOK AT ME.
MUK: GIVE IT BACK.
ALIEN: GET AWAY.
MUK: COME BACK HERE!
YOU HEARD ME,
YOU CHEATING, NO-GOOD LIAR!
KREM: THERE.
THAT ONE.
ARCHER: I'M SURPRISED YOUR
FRIEND DIDN'T GET ELECTROCUTED.
YOU CAN'T JUST YANK OUT
AN ANTIMATTER INJECTOR
LIKE IT WAS A LIGHT BULB.
WOULD YOU MIND?
I'LL HAVE TO TAKE
THE INJECTOR ASSEMBLY OFFLINE.
[KREM GRUNTS]
WARP-CORE PARTS
ARE IN HIGH DEMAND.
ARCHER: HMM.
EVEN IF YOUR COUSIN
DOES FIND THE VAULT,
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
HE'S GONNA SHARE
THE GOLD WITH YOU?
WE HAVE A CONTRACT.
IF YOU NEVER SEE THE VAULT,
YOU'LL NEVER KNOW WHAT'S IN IT.
HE COULD TRY TO CHEAT YOU
OUT OF YOUR SHARE.
HE WOULDN'T CHEAT ME.
WHAT HAPPENED TO...
"NEVER ALLOW FAMILY
TO STAND IN THE WAY OF PROFIT"?
I'VE SEEN THE WAY
THE OTHERS TREAT YOU.
ONE OF THEM SAID YOU HAVE
NO TALENT FOR BUSINESS.
WHY NOT PROVE THEM WRONG?
I'VE GOT A PROPOSITION FOR YOU.
HELP ME CAPTURE
YOUR ASSOCIATES,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU
WHERE THE VAULT IS.
WE'LL SPLIT THE GOLD, 50-50.
ONCE THEY'RE IN THE BRIG,
YOU CAN FLY OFF A WEALTHY MAN.
YOU SAID YOU'VE ALWAYS DREAMED
OF HAVING YOUR OWN SHIP.
HOW DO I KNOW
YOU WON'T DOUBLE-CROSS ME?
ARCHER: YOU'RE THE ONE
HOLDING THE GUN.
THINK ABOUT IT.
NO MORE TAKING ORDERS,
GETTING STUCK
WITH THE MENIAL WORK.
I'LL EVEN THROW IN
THE VULCAN FEMALE.
OHH.
SO WHAT'LL IT BE?
OPPORTUNITIES LIKE THIS
DON'T COME ALONG EVERY DAY.
GET BACK TO WORK.
[SIGHS]
IT'S YOUR LOSS.
ALIEN: WHERE IS THE VAULT?
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
[BARKS]
I CAN'T LOCK ON
TO ITS LANGUAGE.
MUK: IT'S A LOWER LIFE-FORM,
YOU FOOL.
PROBABLY THE CAPTAIN'S
NEXT MEAL.
ALIEN: DON'T BE SO SURE.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF ITS EARS.
MUK: I COULD GET
SEVERAL BARS OF LATINUM
FOR THIS CREATURE
AT THE MALURZIAN ZOO.
ULIS: THERE'S NOTHING HERE.
LET'S SEARCH
THE OTHER QUARTERS.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF VAULT HUNTING
FOR ONE DAY.
YOU TWO HAVE FUN.
[CHUCKLES]
WHO'S THERE?
ONE OF THE ALIENS IS AWAKE!
[QUIET TAP]
TUCKER: AAH!
[GRUNTING]
MUK: AAH!
AAH!
ULIS: WHY AREN'T YOU ASLEEP?
UGH!
[GROANS]
ARCHER: WHAT'S NEXT?
WHERE DO YOU EXPECT ME
TO PUT IT?
THERE'S HARDLY ANY ROOM
LEFT ON YOUR SHIP.
I THINK IT'S TIME
YOU DECIDED
WHAT YOU REALLY
WANT TO KEEP.
KREM: UH, I'LL ASK ULIS.
ARCHER: CAN'T YOU MAKE
A SIMPLE DECISION BY YOURSELF?
IF YOU WANT TO RUN
YOUR OWN SHIP SOMEDAY,
MAYBE YOU SHOULD START
SHOWING A LITTLE INITIATIVE.
KREM: I'M NOT
THE ONE IN CHARGE.
ARCHER: AND YOU NEVER WILL BE
WITH THAT ATTITUDE.
ULIS: WHO'S THIS?
ARCHER: MY CHIEF ENGINEER.
ULIS: WHY IS HE AWAKE?
ARCHER: DON'T ASK ME.
ULIS: ARE THERE OTHERS?
ARCHER: I HAVEN'T
SEEN ANYBODY. YOU?
KREM: UH...
ALIEN: THE ANESTHESIA
ISN'T SUPPOSED TO WEAR OFF
FOR ANOTHER TWO HOURS.
MAYBE WE USED
THE WRONG DOSAGE.
THERE COULD BE OTHERS AWAKE.
WE SHOULD LEAVE.
ULIS: NOT WITHOUT THE GOLD.
MUK: FORGET THE GOLD.
WE'LL NEVER FIND IT.
ULIS: IF YOU WANT TO LEAVE,
TAKE ONE OF THEIR SHUTTLECRAFT.
I'LL BE HAPPY
TO KEEP YOUR SHARE.
YOU EXPECT ME TO GO
EMPTY-HANDED?
YOU CAN KEEP THE SHUTTLECRAFT
AND THE FEMALES.
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
ULIS: IT'LL HAVE TO BE.
MUK: YOU'LL REGRET THIS, ULIS.
GET OUT.
GRISH, HELP ME WITH THE WOMEN.
TUCKER: WAIT.
I'LL SHOW YOU THE VAULT.
ARCHER: TRIP.
TUCKER: LEAVE THE WOMEN HERE,
AND I'LL LET YOU HAVE THE GOLD.
ARCHER: NOT ANOTHER WORD,
COMMANDER. THAT'S AN ORDER.
TUCKER: I'M NOT LETTING THEM
TAKE MY WIFE.
ULIS: WIFE?
KREM: SHE'S NOT THE ONE WITH
THE POINTY EARS, IS SHE?
TUCKER: NO. HER NAME'S HOSHI.
AND YOU'RE GONNA KEEP
YOUR FILTHY HANDS OFF HER.
DO WE HAVE A DEAL?
ARCHER: YOU TAKE THEM
ANYWHERE NEAR THAT VAULT,
AND I'LL THROW YOU IN THE BRIG
FOR INSUBORDINATION.
TUCKER: YOU DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT THIS CREW.
ALL YOU CARE ABOUT
IS YOUR PRECIOUS GOLD.
ARCHER: I'M WARNING YOU, TRIP.
YOU'RE A GREEDY SON OF A BITCH.
ARCHER: WHAT'S YOUR WIFE WORTH?
5 BARS OF GOLD, MAYBE 6?
LET THEM TAKE HOSHI,
AND I'LL GIVE YOU 10.
TUCKER: WHAT?!
ALL RIGHT, 15.
AAH!
ULIS: ENOUGH!
ARCHER: UGH!
ULIS: I ACCEPT YOUR OFFER.
TUCKER: YOU'LL LEAVE THE WOMEN?
ULIS: YOU HAVE MY WORD
AS A BUSINESSMAN.
TUCKER: FOLLOW ME.
ULIS: WAIT HERE. I'LL GO.
MUK: SO YOU CAN CHEAT US
OUT OF OUR SHARE?
HIDE IT IN THE BOTTOM
OF YOUR BAG?
I PLAN TO COUNT EVERY BAR
OF THAT GOLD MYSELF
BEFORE IT LEAVES THE VAULT.
ULIS: WE'LL COUNT IT LATER.
OH, I KNOW YOU TOO WELL, ULIS.
GRISH: IF HE'S GOING,
I'M GOING.
ME TOO!
ULIS: WE CAN'T ALL GO.
TIME'S RUNNING OUT.
SOMEONE HAS TO STAY
AND FINISH LOADING THE SHIP.
GRISH: THAT'S KREM'S JOB.
KREM: I'M TIRED OF
DOING THIS JOB!
I DON'T WANT TO DO
ALL THE MENIAL WORK!
KREM!
KREM: IT'S TIME THAT I
SHOWED A LITTLE INITIATIVE!
I HAVE THE LOBES FOR BUSINESS!
YOU JUST NEVER GIVE ME
THE CHANCE TO PROVE IT!
GET BACK TO WORK!
YES, COUSIN.
[LAUGHTER]
YOU...SURE TOLD HIM.
KREM: GET BACK TO WORK.
[GROANS]
MY BACK.
KREM: WHAT ABOUT IT?
ARCHER: I THINK
I PULLED A MUSCLE.
IT'S AN OLD WATER-POLO INJURY.
FLARES UP EVERY NOW AND THEN.
I JUST NEED TO REST.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY TIME.
IF ULIS COMES BACK
AND WE'RE NOT FINISHED...
THEN YOU'D BETTER GET WORKING.
[KREM GRUNTS]
ULIS: WHERE ARE WE GOING?
TUCKER: BOTTOM DECK.
MUK: WE ALREADY LOOKED THERE.
TUCKER: YOU OBVIOUSLY
DIDN'T LOOK IN THE RIGHT PLACE.
ULIS: AFTER YOU.
T'POL: HAVE YOU
COME TO RESCUE ME?
HOW DID YOU WAKE UP?
T'POL: WHATEVER PUT
THE OTHERS TO SLEEP
DIDN'T AFFECT ME
IN THE SAME WAY.
MY BODY WORKS DIFFERENTLY
THAN THE HUMANS.
HUMANS?
T'POL: THAT'S THE NAME
OF THEIR SPECIES.
THEY'RE A TERRIBLE RACE--
DECEITFUL, CRUEL.
WHY DO YOU LIVE WITH THEM?
IT WASN'T MY CHOICE.
I'M A CAPTIVE HERE.
THEY'VE ENSLAVED ME.
PLEASE TAKE ME WITH YOU.
KREM: YOU WOULD MAKE
A HANDSOME WIFE.
[CHUCKLES]
DO YOU...
KNOW HOW TO PERFORM OO-MOX?
T'POL: I'M WELL-TRAINED
IN THE ARTS OF PLEASURE.
KREM: OHH...
T'POL: BUT I'M NOT
FAMILIAR WITH OO-MOX.
KREM: MY LOBES.
STROKE...MY LOBES.
[KREM GASPING]
T'POL: LIKE THIS?
KREM: YES.
T'POL: AND THIS?
KREM: OH, YES!
ULIS: HAVEN'T WE BEEN
THROUGH THIS SECTION?
TUCKER: NOT YET.
ULIS: I RECOGNIZE THAT CONDUIT.
TUCKER: WE HAVE A THOUSAND
CONDUITS LIKE THAT ON THIS SHIP.
MUK: WE'RE GOING IN CIRCLES.
TUCKER: THIS WAY.
GRISH: ISN'T THERE A MORE
DIRECT ROUTE?
TUCKER: THAT'S THE BEAUTY
OF THIS THING.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO FIND
UNLESS YOU KNOW
EXACTLY WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
ULIS: HOW MUCH FURTHER?
TUCKER: KEEP YOUR SHIRT ON.
IT'S CLOSE.
TUCKER: WATCH YOUR HEAD.
MUK: IS THIS YOUR PLAN--
TO WALK US TO DEATH?
ULIS: IS THIS
SOME KIND OF TRICK?
TUCKER: RELAX. WE'RE HERE.
ALIEN: OH!
GRISH: THE VAULT?
IT'S ALL YOURS.
ULIS: OPEN IT. OPEN IT!
BETTER LET ME GO IN FIRST.
ULIS: WHY?
KNOWING CAPTAIN ARCHER,
HE'S PROBABLY RIGGED THE PLACE
WITH BOOBY TRAPS.
JUST GIVE ME A FEW MINUTES
TO CHECK IT OUT.
MUK: NO!
YOU COULD HAVE A WEAPON
HIDDEN IN THERE.
ULIS: I'LL GO.
MUK: NO!
NOT WITHOUT ME, YOU WON'T.
YOU'LL FILL YOUR POCKETS
WITH GOLD.
ULIS: TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
GRISH: WE DON'T HAVE ALL DAY!
ULIS: GET AWAY FROM THAT HATCH!
OUT OF MY WAY!
GRISH: THIEF!
I WANT MY SHARE!
ULIS: IT'S MINE!
MUK: GET BACK OR I'LL
GNAW YOUR HANDS OFF!
GRISH: MY GOLD! MY GOLD!
ULIS: IT'S A TRAP!
UGH!
TUCKER: SORRY, FELLAS.
BANK MUST BE CLOSED TODAY.
ARCHER: DID IT WORK?
T'POL: PERFECTLY.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
DO YOU HAVE THE KEY?
T'POL: NOT THAT INTERESTING?
NO SENSE OF HUMOR?
ALWAYS COMPLAINING?
ARCHER: I'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU.
T'POL: HOW?
ARCHER: 5 BARS OF GOLD?
OPEN THESE THINGS, SUBCOMMANDER.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ALIEN WHIMPERS]
[PORTHOS WHINING]
OH, YES.
YEAH, PORTHOS. MM.
YES. YOU OK?
ARCHER: I'M GOING
TO BE CONTACTING
THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND,
AS WELL AS STARFLEET.
IF YOU COME WITHIN A LIGHT-YEAR
OF ANY ONE OF OUR SHIPS,
YOU WON'T KNOW WHAT HIT YOU.
KREM: YOU'LL NEVER
SEE US AGAIN.
ARCHER: IF YOU WANT
TO BE UNSHACKLED,
YOU MIGHT THINK
ABOUT SHOWING KREM HERE
A LITTLE MORE RESPECT.
MUK: VERMIN!
ULIS: RELEASE ME.
AND I'LL FORGET
THIS EVER HAPPENED.
KREM: LATER.
MAYBE. IF YOU'RE NICE.
LET ME GO, YOU IDIOT!
SHUT UP!
KREM: ARE YOU SURE YOU WANT
TO STAY HERE WITH THE HUMANS?
WITH MY SHIP AND YOUR TALENTS,
WE COULD BUILD A VAST FORTUNE.
ULIS: I'LL LET YOU HAVE
MY LATINUM PEN--
THE ONE YOU'VE ALWAYS HAD
YOUR EYE ON.
KREM: NO, THANKS.
ULIS: MY BEETLE SNUFF
COLLECTION?
KREM: MAKES ME SNEEZE.
ULIS: NAME YOUR PRICE.
WHATEVER HE OFFERS YOU,
I'LL DOUBLE IT.
KREM! WE'RE FAMILY.
MUK: I KNOW A BOLIAN FEMALE.
I COULD INTRODUCE YOU.