ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
I'M BEGINNING TO WONDER
IF INVITING THE KREETASSANS
ABOARD WAS SUCH A GOOD IDEA.
IT'S BEEN A CHALLENGING MORNING,
TO SAY THE LEAST.
KREETASSAN:
[ SPEAKING KREETASSAN ]
ARCHER: DID YOU GET THAT?
SATO: TOSTKA -- "INSULT."
SOME KIND OF AN INSULT?
T'POL: HE'S INSULTING US
OR WE INSULTED THEM?
SATO: I'M NOT SURE.
KREETASSAN: TOSTKA!
ARCHER:
ASK WHAT WE DID WRONG.
SATO: [ SPEAKING KREETASSAN ]
KREETASSAN:
[ SPEAKING KREETASSAN ]
ARCHER: WELL?
SATO: "YOU EAT LIKE YOU MATE"?
TUCKER:
YOU SURE THAT THING'S WORKING?
KREETASSAN:
[ SPEAKING KREETASSAN ]
SATO: I THINK
THEY WANT TO LEAVE.
T'POL: THAT MUCH IS OBVIOUS.
ARCHER: WHATEVER WE'VE DONE
TO OFFEND YOU...
I APOLOGIZE.
SATO: [ SPEAKING KREETASSAN ]
KREETASSAN:
[ SPEAKING KREETASSAN ]
TUCKER: WELL, THIS IS ONE
FOR THE BOOKS.
BRIEFEST FIRST CONTACT.
RUSSELL WATSON:
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ STATIC CRACKLES, PINGING ]
SATO: DOES ANYBODY HEAR THAT?
TUCKER: WHAT? THE STATIC?
SATO: FREQUENCY DISTORTIONS
MIXED IN WITH THE STATIC.
MAYWEATHER: YOU'VE GOT
BETTER EARS THAN WE DO.
SATO: IT'S COMING
FROM THE COM SYSTEM.
T'POL: HAVE YOU RUN
A DIAGNOSTIC?
SATO: TWICE.
GUESS TODAY IS JUST NOT MY DAY.
MAYWEATHER: HOW'S
THE TRANSLATION COMING ALONG?
SATO: SLOWLY.
HWAJAT-- THEIR WORD FOR "EAT."
MAYWEATHER:
WHAT ABOUT IT?
SATO: WITH THE EMPHASIS ON
THE FIRST SYLLABLE -- HWA-jat --
IT MEANS "TO MATE."
MAYWEATHER: I CAN SEE
HOW THAT MIGHT CAUSE
SOME CONFUSION OVER DINNER.
SATO: CONTEXT IS CRITICAL
IN EVERY LANGUAGE,
BUT KREETASSAN HAS
THE MOST SUBTLE VARIATIONS
I'VE EVER SEEN.
THE SAME WORD CAN HAVE
A DOZEN DIFFERENT MEANINGS.
T'POL: WE RELY ON YOU
TO RECOGNIZE
THE DIFFERENCE, ENSIGN.
SATO: YOU THINK IT WAS MY FAULT?
T'POL: I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
SATO: YOU IMPLIED IT.
T'POL: I SIMPLY NOTED
THAT LINGUISTIC MATTERS
FALL WITHIN
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY.
FOR ALL WE KNOW,
IT WAS MR. TUCKER'S TABLE
MANNERS THAT OFFENDED THEM.
SATO: BUT YOU THINK IF
I PICKED UP THE LANGUAGE FASTER,
THEY MIGHT HAVE NOT
STORMED OFF THE SHIP.
T'POL: THERE'S NO NEED
TO REACT EMOTIONALLY.
TRY TO LEARN FROM FAILURE.
IT COULD HELP YOUR NEXT FIRST
CONTACT BE MORE SUCCESSFUL.
SATO: THANKS.
COMMANDER, I'M PICKING UP
SOME KIND OF INTERFERENCE
ON THE COM SYSTEM.
A HIGH-FREQUENCY DISTORTION.
TUCKER: IS IT A PROBLEM?
SATO: MOSTLY JUST IRRITATING.
TUCKER: I'LL TRACK IT DOWN
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
SATO: THANKS.
TUCKER: IS HE IN THERE?
T'POL: YES.
TUCKER: HOW'S HIS MOOD?
T'POL: NOW MIGHT NOT BE
THE BEST TIME.
TUCKER: I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES.
[ DOORBELL CHIMES ]
ARCHER: IT BETTER BE IMPORTANT.
TUCKER: PRIME RIB TONIGHT.
WITH REAL HORSERADISH.
ARCHER: THANKS. I'LL HAVE
THE STEWARD SEND SOME UP.
THOUGHT WE'D SET A COURSE
FOR THIS BROWN-DWARF SYSTEM.
LOOKS INTERESTING.
TUCKER: I CAN'T WAIT.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WHY DON'T WE SHOOT
A LITTLE NINE-BALL?
YOU CAN BREAK.
ARCHER: MAYBE LATER.
TUCKER: I WAS GOING TO SAVE THIS
FOR A RAINY DAY, BUT...
STANFORD VERSUS TEXAS.
ARCHER: THE FINALS?
TUCKER: FRESH OUT OF
THE SUBSPACE MAILBAG.
YOU'VE BEEN THREATENING
TO TEACH ME
THE FINER POINTS OF THE GAME.
UNLESS YOU'RE TOO BUSY
WITH YOUR BROWN DWARVES.
[ DISTANT CLANK ]
PORTHOS: [ BARKING ]
MAYWEATHER: WHAT IF THEY JUST
DON'T LIKE BEING TOUCHED?
REMEMBER HOW UNCOMFORTABLE
THEY LOOKED
WHEN THE CAPTAIN TRIED
TO SHAKE THEIR HANDS?
REED: THEY LOOKED THAT WAY
THE ENTIRE TIME.
BESIDES, THEY DIDN'T
REALLY LOSE THEIR TEMPER
UNTIL THEY ARRIVED HERE
IN THE MESS HALL.
MAYWEATHER: ARE YOU STAYING
FOR THE MOVIE TONIGHT?
REED: WHAT'S PLAYING?
MAYWEATHER: UH, "WAGES OF FEAR."
CLASSIC FRENCH FILM.
REED: MM.
MAYWEATHER: NO, YOU'LL LIKE IT.
THINGS BLOW UP.
REED: OH. SOUNDS FUN.
MAYWEATHER: HOSHI?
SATO: NO, THANKS.
I'M TURNING IN EARLY.
REED: WE MIGHT NEED
A TRANSLATOR.
THOSE SUBTITLES GO BY
PRETTY FAST.
SATO: I'VE HAD ENOUGH
LANGUAGE PROBLEMS FOR ONE DAY.
[ SOFT THUDDING ]
ROSTOV: WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO SIT IN THE BACK.
KELLY: ONE MINUTE.
ROSTOV:
I HATE MISSING THE BEGINNING.
KELLY: IT'S ON THE COMPUTER.
YOU CAN WATCH IT
WHENEVER YOU WANT.
ROSTOV: IT'S NOT THE SAME.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO BACK
AND SEE THE FIRST PART
AFTER YOU KNOW HOW IT ENDS.
KELLY: [ LAUGHS ]
THE POWER JUST WENT OUT
ON "D" DECK.
CARGO BAY 2.
THE LIGHTING GRID'S DOWN.
ROSTOV: IT'S PROBABLY JUST
A BLOWN RELAY.
LEAVE IT FOR THE NIGHT SHIFT.
KELLY:
IF IT'S JUST A BLOWN RELAY,
IT'LL TAKE YOU
10 MINUTES TO FIX.
HERE.
THE COM'S OUT, TOO.
REED: TWO AND A HALF HOURS?
MAYWEATHER:
TWO HOURS AND 24 MINUTES.
REED: THAT SEEMS
AWFULLY LONG FOR A MOVIE
ABOUT FOUR MEN IN A TRUCK.
MAYWEATHER: YOU'LL BE
ON THE EDGE OF YOUR SEAT.
REED: YOU PROMISED ME
EXPLOSIONS.
MAYWEATHER: DON'T WORRY.
REED: THIS IS ALL WRONG.
EXCUSE ME. EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU.
REED TO BRIDGE.
MAN: GO AHEAD, LIEUTENANT.
REED: WE'RE TRYING TO WATCH
A MOVIE DOWN HERE.
BUT INSTEAD, WE'RE BEING
TREATED TO A VIEW OF YOU.
SO UNLESS YOU'RE PLANNING
ON GIVING US
A LITTLE SONG AND DANCE,
MAYBE YOU COULD SEE
WHAT'S GONE WRONG.
ARCHER: COME ON. COME ON.
YES!
TUCKER: HOW DEEP'S THE POOL?
ARCHER: DEEP ENOUGH SO THAT
NO ONE CAN TOUCH THE BOTTOM.
TUCKER: I DIDN'T KNOW
IT WAS SUCH A ROUGH GAME.
ARCHER: THINK OF IT
AS ONE PART BASKETBALL,
ONE PART SWIMMING...
AND ONE PART WRESTLING.
TUCKER: AND I THOUGHT IT WAS
JUST A BUNCH OF GUYS
SCREWING AROUND IN A POOL.
HMM.
[ SQUISHING ]
[ SQUISHES ]
[ BEEPS ]
KELLY: ENGINEERING.
MICHAEL, IS THAT YOU?
HELLO?
TUCKER: NICE GOAL!
DID YOU SEE THE WAY
NUMBER 12 SET HIM UP?
HE'S CALLED
THE POINT MAN, RIGHT?
ARCHER: VERY GOOD.
I TOLD YOU.
BEST SPORT IN THE WORLD.
TUCKER: I'LL STILL TAKE
A GREAT OFF-TACKLE RUN
OUT OF THE BACKFIELD,
BUT I CAN SEE
HOW YOU CAN GET HOOKED ON THIS.
ARCHER: THANKS
FOR THINKING OF IT.
TUCKER: MY PLEASURE.
NOW KEEP WATCHING
WHILE TEXAS TROUNCES
YOUR SORRY CALIFORNIA BUTTS.
ARCHER: YOU HAVEN'T WATCHED
THE END OF THIS, HAVE YOU?
TUCKER: OF COURSE NOT.
KELLY: HELLO?
TUCKER: WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
ARCHER: OH, NUMBER 8 ON TEXAS
JUST FOULED ONE OF MY BOYS.
HE'S GONNA BE EJECTED
FOR 20 SECONDS.
TUCKER: IS THAT FAIR?
IT GIVES YOUR GUYS AN ADVANTAGE.
ARCHER: WELL, THAT'S THE POINT.
TUCKER: [ GROANS ]
ARCHER: [ LAUGHS ]
I DON'T SUPPOSE
IT'D BE PRACTICAL
TO PUT A POOL ON THE SHIP.
TUCKER: WELL, I WOULDN'T WANT
TO BE TAKING A SWIM
IF THE GRAVITY PLATING
WENT OFF-LINE.
ARCHER: NO. NO.
TUCKER: [ LAUGHS ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
KELLY: KELLY TO THE CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
KELLY: SIR, I'M IN
CARGO BAY 2, AND...
THERE'S SOME KIND
OF LIFE-FORM IN HERE.
ARCHER: LIFE-FORM?
KELLY: IT'S GOT ROSTOV, SIR.
HE'S STILL CONSCIOUS,
BUT HE CAN'T -- [GASPS]
ARCHER: CREWMAN?
[ STATIC CRACKLES ]
ARCHER: WEAPONS TO STUN.
REED: CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: SIR?
REED: CAREFUL.
KELLY: [ GROANS SOFTLY ]
ARCHER: THE LIGHT.
REED: SHE'S ALIVE.
ROSTOV: CAPTAIN?
[ GROANS ]
LEAVE.
ARCHER: CREWMAN?
ROSTOV: LEAVE.
REED: CAPTAIN!
ARCHER: [ GRUNTS ]
AH! AH!
LIFE-FORM: [ SCREECHES ]
[ SCREECHING ]
ARCHER: AH!
[ SQUISHING ]
TUCKER: [ GROANS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
GET OUT OF HERE!
GO!
[ SQUISHES ]
ZABEL: [ GRUNTS ]
TUCKER: AH!
REED: THIS THING
APPEARS TO BE GROWING.
THERE'S NO TELLING IF IT'LL
GET OUT OF THE CARGO BAY.
I RECOMMEND WE EVACUATE
THE ENTIRE DECK.
SATO: HOW DID IT GET ON BOARD?
MAYWEATHER: THE LAST TIME
WE OPENED THE AIRLOCK,
WE WERE DOCKED
WITH THE KREETASSANS.
REED: YOU THINK THEY LEFT US
A LITTLE SOUVENIR?
T'POL: OUR ENCOUNTER
DIDN'T GO WELL,
BUT I DOUBT WE GAVE THEM
REASON TO ATTACK US.
WE'RE NOT EVEN CERTAIN
THAT THE ORGANISM'S HOSTILE.
REED: YOU DIDN'T SEE THAT THING
GO AFTER THE CAPTAIN!
IT SEEMED HOSTILE ENOUGH TO ME.
MAYWEATHER:
THE KREETASSANS MIGHT KNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT THIS THING.
I CAN START SCANNING
FOR THEIR SHIP,
TRY TO PICK UP THEIR WARP TRAIL.
T'POL: WE'LL NEED TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THEM BETTER THAN LAST TIME.
SATO: I'LL DO MY BEST.
[ BEEPS ]
T'POL: T'POL TO DR. PHLOX.
REPORT.
PHLOX: I'M PREPARING TO EXAMINE
THE SPECIMEN.
WOULD YOU CARE TO OBSERVE?
T'POL: YES. STAND BY.
PHLOX: YOU'LL NOTE
THAT EVEN THOUGH
IT'S BEEN SEVERED
FROM ITS BODY,
IT SURVIVES INDEPENDENTLY,
NOT UNLIKE THE COMMON EARTHWORM
OR THE NEETHIAN CRADLEFISH.
REED: DO YOU THINK
THAT'S WISE, DOCTOR?
PHLOX: POSSIBLY NOT.
BUT I'M GOING TO NEED
A TISSUE SAMPLE
IF I HOPE TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT ITS PHYSIOLOGY.
THAT'LL BE QUITE ENOUGH.
THIS IS NO EARTHWORM.
T'POL: DOCTOR?
PHLOX: LOOK AT
THE SYNAPTIC ACTIVITY.
THIS ORGANISM POSSESSES A VERY
SOPHISTICATED NERVOUS SYSTEM.
IT COULD BE CAPABLE OF
HIGHER MENTAL FUNCTIONS.
SATO: IF IT'S INTELLIGENT, MAYBE
WE CAN COMMUNICATE WITH IT.
THE FREQUENCY DISTORTIONS --
THEY LOOK A LOT LIKE
THE PHONETIC PATTERNS
IN CERTAIN ANDORIAN DIALECTS.
REED: WITH ALL
DUE RESPECT, HOSHI,
WE'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT
NOUNS AND VERBS HERE.
IT COULD TAKE YOU DAYS TO
LEARN A LANGUAGE LIKE THAT,
EVEN IF IT IS ONE.
SATO: WHAT OTHER CHOICE
DO WE HAVE?
GIVE ME A CHANCE.
T'POL: I'M SORRY, ENSIGN.
THERE ISN'T ENOUGH TIME.
SATO: SUBCOMMANDER --
T'POL: WE NEED TO NEUTRALIZE IT.
QUICKLY.
YOU SAID PHASE PISTOLS
HAD NO EFFECT.
REED: NONE THAT I COULD TELL.
T'POL: THEN I SUGGEST YOU FIND
A METHOD THAT DOES.
PHLOX: IF I MAY...
THE ORGANISM
IS HIGHLY PHOTOSENSITIVE.
A SUSTAINED BURST
OF E.M. RADIATION
MIGHT BE ENOUGH
TO STUN THE CREATURE.
T'POL: CAN YOU ASSEMBLE
SOME E.M. EMITTERS?
REED: IT'LL TAKE A FEW MINUTES.
ALL: [ SOFT GROANING ]
ROSTOV: WHY DOESN'T IT
JUST KILL US?
TUCKER: TAKE IT EASY.
ARCHER: I'M SURE T'POL
AND MALCOLM ARE DOING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN
TO GET US OUT OF HERE.
CAN EITHER OF YOU...
SEE CREWMAN KELLY?
ROSTOV: YES, SIR.
ARCHER: HOW'S SHE LOOK?
ROSTOV: SHE'S STILL BREATHING.
TUCKER: ZABEL'S
STILL UNCONSCIOUS.
ROSTOV: CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: YEAH?
ROSTOV: I IMAGINE
IN A SITUATION LIKE THIS
THEY'D CANCEL THE MOVIE.
TUCKER: [ LAUGHS ]
ARCHER: YEAH, I IMAGINE SO.
ROSTOV: I REALLY
WANTED TO SEE IT.
[ FRENCH ACCENT ] YVES MONTAND
DRIVING EXPLOSIVES
THROUGH THE MOUNTAINS.
ARCHER: I'LL MAKE SURE THEY
RESCHEDULE IT FOR NEXT WEEK.
ROSTOV:
[ NORMAL VOICE ] THANK YOU, SIR.
LIFE-FORM: [ SCREECHING ]
PHLOX: IT'S WORKING.
ALL: [ GROANING ]
REED: BRIDGE, SOMETHING'S WRONG.
PHLOX: SHUT OFF THE EMITTERS.
REED: DOCTOR?
PHLOX: SHUT THEM OFF!
[ GROANING CONTINUES ]
REED: OFF.
[ GROANING STOPS ]
T'POL: WHAT HAPPENED?
PHLOX: THEIR NERVOUS SYSTEMS
APPEAR TO BE LINKED
TO THE ORGANISM'S.
THEY'RE SHARING AUTONOMIC
FUNCTIONS, NEURAL IMPULSES.
IF WE CONTINUE FIRING,
WE COULD END UP KILLING
OUR OWN PEOPLE.
[ BEEPS ]
T'POL: MR. REED,
WITHDRAW YOUR TEAM.
REED: UNDERSTOOD.
PHLOX: THE RATE OF SYMBIOSIS
IS INCREASING.
IF WE DON'T FIND A WAY
TO EXTRACT THEM SOON,
THEIR SYSTEMS WILL BE TOO
INTEGRATED WITH THE CREATURE.
I WON'T BE ABLE
TO SEPARATE THEM.
T'POL: YOU WANTED A CHANCE
TO COMMUNICATE.
I SUGGEST YOU BEGIN.
HOW MUCH TIME DO THEY HAVE?
PHLOX: A FEW HOURS AT MOST.
THEIR METABOLIC RATES
ARE DROPPING --
TEMPERATURE, RESPIRATION.
REED: THERE MUST BE SOME WAY
TO CUT THEM OUT OF THERE.
PHLOX: I'M NOT SURE
IF YOU APPRECIATE
HOW ALIEN THIS CREATURE IS.
IT'S NOT ATTACKING OUR CREWMEN,
IT'S TRYING TO INTEGRATE THEM
INTO ITSELF.
REED: THE END RESULT'S THE SAME.
PHLOX: AT SOME POINT
IN THE VERY NEAR FUTURE,
THERE WON'T BE SIX LIFE-FORMS
IN THAT CARGO BAY.
THERE'LL ONLY BE ONE.
REED: IF THAT THING
CONTINUES TO GROW,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO FIND
A WAY TO CONTAIN IT.
T'POL: DO YOU HAVE A SUGGESTION?
REED: STARFLEET'S BEEN WORKING
ON CREATING
A STABLE E.M. BARRIER
FOR THE LAST FIVE YEARS.
T'POL: A FORCE FIELD?
REED: RIGHT.
THEY JUST HAVEN'T FOUND A WAY
TO CONTROL THE PARTICLE DENSITY.
ALL THE SPECS
ARE IN THE DATABASE.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO JURY-RIG
A PROTOTYPE OF MY OWN.
T'POL: AND?
REED: I'VE GOT IT STABLE ENOUGH
TO ABSORB A PHASE-PISTOL BLAST
60% OF THE TIME.
I THINK I CAN IMPROVE ON THAT.
T'POL: I SUGGEST
YOU WORK QUICKLY.
MAYWEATHER:
I THINK I FOUND THEM.
T'POL: WHERE?
MAYWEATHER:
0.52 LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE.
T'POL: LAY IN A COURSE.
MAYWEATHER: I ALREADY HAVE.
I'VE BEEN SENDING OUT HAILS,
BUT WE'RE STILL
OUT OF COM RANGE.
T'POL: LET ME KNOW
AS SOON AS THEY RESPOND.
ANY PROGRESS?
SATO: BELIEVE ME,
YOU'D BE THE FIRST TO KNOW.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S FRUSTRATING.
I'M NOT HAVING A LOT OF LUCK.
T'POL: THE SITUATION REQUIRES
EXPERTISE, NOT LUCK.
SATO: THEN MAYBE I DON'T HAVE
THE EXPERTISE.
T'POL: IF YOU DON'T, NO ONE ELSE
ABOARD ENTERPRISE DOES.
SATO: I'M DOING MY BEST.
T'POL: IT WAS YOUR SUGGESTION
THAT WE ATTEMPT
TO COMMUNICATE WITH IT.
IF YOU DON'T THINK
THAT'S POSSIBLE,
WE'LL HAVE TO FIND
ANOTHER SOLUTION.
SATO:
I'VE MADE A LITTLE PROGRESS.
BUT OUR TRANSLATION MATRIX
ISN'T DESIGNED FOR THIS.
LOOK AT IT.
IT'S MORE LIKE A CALCULUS
EQUATION THAN A LANGUAGE.
T'POL: MATHEMATICS IS SOMETIMES
CONSIDERED A FORM OF LANGUAGE.
SATO: WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY IS
THAT I COULD USE HELP
FROM SOMEONE
WITH A BACKGROUND
IN HIGHER MATHEMATICS.
T'POL: PERHAPS I CAN ASSIST YOU.
TUCKER: THE TEXAS GOALIE
CAN'T BLOCK TO HIS RIGHT
BECAUSE HE KEEPS
HIS HANDS TOO DEEP.
ARCHER: HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
ROSTOV: CAPTAIN...
I KNOW IT, TOO.
AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
ANYTHING ABOUT WATER POLO.
ARCHER: [ GRUNTS ]
IT'S THIS LIFE-FORM.
IT'S LINKING US
TOGETHER SOMEHOW.
TUCKER: WE GOT TO GET OUT!
ARCHER: CALM DOWN.
TUCKER: THIS THING'S GOTTEN
INSIDE OUR HEADS!
[ GROANS ]
ARCHER: TRIP, D--
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M THINKING ABOUT?
TUCKER: [ GASPING ]
TUCKER: NOW IS NOT THE TIME TO
BE THINKING ABOUT THE REGIONALS.
ARCHER: TRIP...
TUCKER: SENIOR YEAR.
NORTH AMERICAN REGIONALS
AGAINST PRINCETON.
WE...
I MEAN, YOU WERE DOWN BY
TWO GOALS, UNDER A MINUTE LEFT.
ARCHER: AND WHAT WAS I THINKING?
WHAT WAS I THINKING?
TUCKER: [ GASPING ]
YOU THOUGHT...
YOU COULD WIN...
EVERY GAME.
YOU ALWAYS THOUGHT
YOU COULD WIN.
NO MATTER HOW FAR BEHIND
YOU WERE.
ARCHER: AND WE DID.
WE WENT ON TO THE FINALS
THAT YEAR.
AS SOON AS YOU GIVE UP,
THE GAME'S LOST.
REED: HOW'S OUR LITTLE FRIEND?
PHLOX: FAST ASLEEP.
IT APPEARS TO HAVE ENTERED
A DORMANT STATE.
PROBABLY A REACTION TO THE SHOCK
OF BEING SEVERED
FROM THE LARGER ORGANISM.
REED: BUT IT'S ALIVE?
PHLOX: VERY MUCH SO.
REED: GOOD.
NOW, IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'D LIKE TO RUN
A FEW TESTS OF MY OWN.
PHLOX: WHAT KIND OF TESTS?
REED: I NEED TO DETERMINE
HOW MUCH BIOELECTRIC STRESS
IT CAN TOLERATE.
PHLOX: MAY I ASK WHY?
REED: I'M TRYING TO CREATE
A FORCE FIELD
TO ISOLATE THE CARGO BAY.
BUT IF IT'S GOING TO WORK,
I HAVE TO CALCULATE
HOW MUCH OF A JOLT IT WILL TAKE
TO REPEL THE ORGANISM
WITHOUT KILLING IT --
OR ANY OF THE PEOPLE IT'S TAKEN.
PHLOX: IF YOU INTEND
TO PUMMEL THIS APPENDAGE
WITH E.M. RADIATION
UNTIL IT CRIES FOR MERCY,
I'M AFRAID I CAN'T PERMIT THAT.
REED: WHY NOT?
PHLOX: THIS IS MORE
THAN JUST A SEVERED LIMB.
IT EXHIBITS ALL THE SIGNS
OF AN INTELLIGENT BEING.
REED: INTELLIGENT BEING OR NOT,
ITS BIG BROTHER
IS IN THE CARGO BAY
STRANGLING THE CAPTAIN
AND FOUR OTHER CREWMEN.
IF WE DON'T DO SOMETHING
TO CONTAIN IT NOW,
IT COULD POSE A THREAT
TO EVERYONE ON BOARD.
PHLOX: THERE ARE
LESS INVASIVE WAYS TO GATHER
THE INFORMATION YOU NEED.
REED: SUCH AS?
PHLOX: A MICROCELLULAR ANALYSIS.
REED: HOW LONG WOULD THAT TAKE?
PHLOX: LESS THAN AN HOUR.
REED; IN LESS THAN AN HOUR,
THAT THING COULD SPREAD
ACROSS HALF A DECK.
PHLOX: I'M WILLING
TO HELP YOU, MR. REED,
BUT NOT IF IT MEANS
TORTURING THIS ORGANISM.
CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG,
BUT ISN'T OUR MISSION
TO TRY TO BETTER UNDERSTAND
UNIQUE FORMS OF LIFE?
REED: NOT IF THEY'RE TRYING
TO KILL THE CAPTAIN.
PHLOX: WE DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THIS
CREATURE'S INTENTIONS.
REED: I ADMIRE
YOUR INTERSPECIES ETHICS,
BUT UNTIL HOSHI TELLS ME
SHE'S FOUND A WAY
TO COMMUNICATE WITH IT,
I HAVE TO ASSUME
ITS INTENTIONS ARE HOSTILE.
NOW...
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
REED: IF YOU WANT
INFORMATION TO HELP YOU
CONSTRUCT YOUR FORCE FIELD,
YOU'LL ACQUIRE IT
UNDER MY SUPERVISION.
REED: I'M SURE I DON'T HAVE
TO REMIND YOU, DOCTOR,
I AM THE RANKING OFFICER HERE.
PHLOX: NOT IN MY SICK BAY.
UNLESS THE CAPTAIN
SAYS OTHERWISE.
REED: THE CAPTAIN IS IN NO
CONDITION TO OFFER AN OPINION.
PHLOX: PRECISELY.
REED: FINE.
YOUR RULES.
BUT WE'D BETTER GET TO IT.
T'POL: WHAT IF WE USED
A BILATERAL ALGORITHM?
SATO: I ALREADY TRIED.
T'POL: DID YOU COMPENSATE
FOR FREQUENCY DRIFT?
SATO: I WOULDN'T BE MUCH
OF A COM OFFICER IF I DIDN'T.
T'POL: ALLOWING YOUR EMOTIONS
TO CONTROL YOU
WON'T HELP SOLVE
THIS PROBLEM, ENSIGN.
SATO: NEITHER WILL QUESTIONING
EVERYTHING I DO.
T'POL: YOU ASKED FOR MY HELP.
SATO: I DIDN'T ASK
FOR YOU TO KEEP COUNT
OF EVERY TIME I MAKE A MISTAKE
OR TO SECOND-GUESS
ALL OF MY DECISIONS.
T'POL: AS FIRST OFFICER,
IT'S MY DUTY TO SUPERVISE YOU.
SATO: THIS GOES BEYOND DUTY,
SUBCOMMANDER.
YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING
OVER MY SHOULDER
EVER SINCE
YOU CAME ON BOARD --
DOUBLE-CHECKING
MY LOG ENTRIES,
MY TRANSLATIONS.
T'POL: IT'S MY JOB.
SATO: IS THAT ALL
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT?
YOU DON'T THINK
I BELONG ON ENTERPRISE, DO YOU?
T'POL: ON THE CONTRARY.
IT WOULD BE A GREAT LOSS
TO STARFLEET
IF YOU WERE NOT A PART
OF THIS CREW.
IF YOU FEEL I'VE BEEN UNFAIR
TO YOU, I APOLOGIZE.
BUT I HOLD YOU
TO A HIGH STANDARD, ENSIGN,
BECAUSE I KNOW
YOU'RE CAPABLE OF ACHIEVING IT.
SHALL WE CONTINUE?
SATO: YES.
UM...
WHY DON'T WE TAKE ANOTHER LOOK
AT THE SUBHARMONICS?
I WAS THINKING WE COULD RUN THEM
THROUGH THE DECRYPTION MATRIX,
SEE IF WE CAN FIND A PATTERN.
ALL I SEE IS NUMBERS, CODES.
T'POL: ANY CODE CAN BE BROKEN.
[ BEEPS ]
KREETASSAN: YOU HAILED US?
MAYWEATHER:
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH.
KREETASSAN:
WE STUDIED YOUR DATABASE.
IT WASN'T DIFFICULT.
MAYWEATHER: OKAY.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
KREETASSAN: YES?
MAYWEATHER: THERE'S AN ALIEN
ORGANISM ON OUR SHIP.
KREETASSAN: YES?
MAYWEATHER: IT CAME ABOARD
AROUND THE SAME TIME WE SAW YOU.
WE WERE HOPING YOU MIGHT KNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
KREETASSAN:
DESCRIBE THIS ORGANISM.
MAYWEATHER: WELL, IT'S BIG.
BUT IT DIDN'T
START OUT THAT WAY.
IT'S LIKE A LARGE MASS
OF TENDRILS.
KREETASSAN: TENDRILS?
MAYWEATHER: LIKE A GIANT WEB.
BUT IT MOVES AND GROWS.
KREETASSAN: WE HAVE SEEN THIS.
MAYWEATHER: WHERE?
KREETASSAN:
ON ITS HOMEWORLD.
PERHAPS IT ATTACHED ITSELF
TO OUR SHIP.
IT WASN'T OUR FAULT.
MAYWEATHER: CAN YOU TELL US
WHERE THIS PLANET IS?
KREETASSAN: APOLOGIZE.
MAYWEATHER: EXCUSE ME?
KREETASSAN: WE WILL SEND YOU
THE COORDINATES,
BUT FIRST YOU MUST APOLOGIZE
TO US FOR YOUR OFFENSE.
MAYWEATHER:
THAT'S THE THING.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT WE DID
TO OFFEND YOU.
KREETASSAN: [ INHALES DEEPLY ]
ON YOUR SHIP, YOU...
PUT FOOD IN YOUR MOUTHS.
MAYWEATHER: YOU MEAN EAT?
KREETASSAN: YES. EAT.
MAYWEATHER: I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IT IS LIKE MATING.
IT IS VERY OFFENSIVE TO US.
MAYWEATHER:
WE WERE JUST EATING.
HOW DO YOU EAT?
KREETASSAN:
WE EAT THE SAME WAY,
BUT NOT IN THE PRESENCE
OF OTHERS.
MAYWEATHER:
I SEE. OKAY.
PLEASE BELIEVE ME.
WE HAD NO IDEA
THAT WOULD BE OFFENSIVE TO YOU.
IT WAS SIMPLY
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
ON BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE CREW,
I SINCERELY APOLOGIZE.
KREETASSAN:
YOUR APOLOGY IS ACCEPTED.
MAYWEATHER: THANK YOU.
NOW, COULD I HAVE
THOSE COORDINATES?
TUCKER: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: YEAH?
TUCKER: I FEEL YOU
DRIFTING AWAY OVER THERE.
ARCHER: YOU AREN'T FEELING
MUCH BETTER THAN I DO.
[ GASPS ]
ROSTOV?
TUCKER: HE'S OUT.
WHEN ZEFRAM COCHRANE...
TALKED ABOUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATION...
DO YOU THINK
THIS IS WHAT HE MEANT?
ARCHER: [ CHUCKLES WEAKLY ]
[ COUGHS ]
SATO: HERE. HERE IT IS.
I FOUND A THIRD SET
OF REPETITIONS.
TRY IT.
JUST A FEW MORE AND THE U.T.
CAN START BUILDING THE SYNTAX.
PHLOX: PHLOX TO T'POL.
T'POL: GO AHEAD.
PHLOX: I KNOW YOU'RE UNDER
A GREAT DEAL OF PRESSURE,
BUT CREWMAN KELLY'S
METABOLIC RATE
HAS DROPPED TO A CRITICAL LEVEL.
WHATEVER YOU'RE PLANNING TO DO,
YOU'D BETTER DO IT SOON.
T'POL: UNDERSTOOD.
MAN: READY, SIR.
REED: THE PARTICLE DENSITY'S
STILL FLUCTUATING.
I THINK THE PROBLEM'S
IN THE LOWER LEFT QUADRANT.
MAN: GOT IT, SIR.
REED: TRY AGAIN.
BETTER.
T'POL: T'POL TO LIEUTENANT REED.
REED: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: WE'VE MADE SOME PROGRESS
ON THE TRANSLATION,
BUT WE'RE GOING TO NEED TO GET
INTO THE CARGO BAY TO TEST IT.
IS THE FORCE FIELD READY?
REED: I'M MAKING
THE FINAL CALIBRATIONS NOW.
T'POL: YOU'LL HAVE
TO DO IT QUICKLY.
DR. PHLOX SAYS OUR PEOPLE
DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
REED: UNDERSTOOD.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN?
[ BEEPING ]
[ ELECTROMAGNETIC HUMMING ]
REED: EMITTER B'S OFF
BY 3.2 MICRONS.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
THE FORCE FIELD'S WORKING,
BUT I CAN'T GUARANTEE
HOW LONG IT'LL HOLD.
HAVE YOU DONE IT?
T'POL: WE'RE ABOUT TO FIND OUT.
[ TONE SOUNDS ]
REED: THAT JUST SOUNDS LIKE
A CONSTANT TONE.
SATO: I'M GOING TO CREATE
DISTORTIONS IN THE TONE.
HOPEFULLY,
THE ORGANISM WILL UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TRYING TO DO.
[ TONE SOUNDS, PINGING ]
[ TONE, PINGING STOP ]
[ TONE, PINGING RESUME ]
LIFE-FORM: [ SCREECHING ]
SATO: COME ON,
JUST A LITTLE MORE.
[ SCREECHING STOPS ]
I THINK I'VE GOT ENOUGH
TO TRY SOMETHING SIMPLE.
T'POL: ASK WHAT IT WANTS.
[ TONE, PINGING RESUME ]
LIFE-FORM: [ SCREECHING ]
SATO: IT'S TALKING TO US.
T'POL: WHAT'S IT SAYING?
ENSIGN?
SATO: HOLD ON!
IT'S GIVING US COORDINATES.
REED: ITS HOMEWORLD?
T'POL: THE KREETASSANS
ALREADY GAVE THEM TO US.
SATO: THESE LOOK MORE LIKE
THE LATITUDE AND LONGITUDE.
I THINK IT'S TRYING TO GIVE US
AN EXACT LOCATION ON THE PLANET.
T'POL: TELL IT
WE'RE TAKING IT BACK.
[ TONE, PINGING RESUME ]
LIFE-FORM: [ SCREECHING ]
PHLOX: COMMANDER TUCKER'S
HEART RATE IS INCREASING.
REED: IS THAT GOOD OR BAD?
PHLOX: IT'S GOOD.
CREWMAN KELLY'S BIOSIGNS
ARE STABILIZING AS WELL.
[ SCREECHING STOPS ]
[ SQUISHING ]
T'POL: LOWER THE FORCE FIELD.
LIEUTENANT.
[ FORCE FIELD POWERS DOWN ]
PHLOX: MEDICAL TEAM,
REPORT TO CARGO BAY 2.
WOMAN: ACKNOWLEDGED.
T'POL: HERE.
SATO: LOOK AT ALL OF THEM.
T'POL: NOT THEM. IT.
THIS IS ALL ONE ORGANISM.
REED: THE PART
THAT GOT ON BOARD --
WHY DID IT TAKE OUR PEOPLE?
PHLOX: HARD TO SAY.
WHEN IT GOT SEPARATED
FROM ITSELF,
PERHAPS IT NEEDED
A PHYSICAL CONNECTION
WITH ANY LIFE-FORM
IT COULD FIND.