[ARCHER COUGHING]
TUCKER: EXCUSE ME?
T'POL: I ASKED IF YOU--
ARCHER: WE HEARD YOU.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
WE'RE SUFFERING
FROM A LACK OF SEXUAL ACTIVITY?
T'POL: STARFLEET
FORBIDS OFFICERS
FROM FRATERNIZING
WITH SUBORDINATES.
UNLESS YOU'VE BEEN
VIOLATING REGULATIONS...
TUCKER: THOSE REGULATIONS
DON'T APPLY TO YOU.
HAVE...
YOU BEEN SUFFERING?
T'POL: ON VULCAN, WE MATE
ONLY ONCE EVERY 7 YEARS.
TUCKER:
THAT'S A HELL OF A DRY SPELL.
ARCHER: WHY ARE YOU SUDDENLY
SO CURIOUS ABOUT THIS?
T'POL: IT'S MY UNDERSTANDING
THAT YOUR MATING RITUAL
IS EFFECTIVE IN EASING TENSION.
THAT HASN'T ALWAYS BEEN
MY EXPERIENCE.
AND YOU THINK THAT
WE NEED OUR TENSIONS EASED?
EFFICIENCY'S DOWN 3%.
MM-HMM.
WE'VE ALL GONE ABOUT 10 MONTHS
WITHOUT A BREAK.
I THINK IT'S NORMAL FOR PEOPLE
TO GET A LITTLE SLOPPY.
PERHAPS IT'S TIME
THE CREW TAKES SHORE LEAVE.
WELL, I LIKE THE SOUND OF THAT.
T'POL: I TOOK THE LIBERTY
OF LOCATING A SUITABLE PLANET
APPROXIMATELY 9 DAYS
FROM OUR PRESENT LOCATION.
IT'S CALLED RISA.
WHAT'S YOUR IDEA OF SUITABLE?
IT'S TROPICAL, WITH AN ABUNDANCE
OF PRISTINE BEACHES.
YOU'LL FIND MORE INFORMATION
IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
IS IT, UH, POPULATED?
T'POL: YES.
BY A HUMANOID CULTURE
RECEPTIVE TO EASING TENSION.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
T'POL: IF YOU'RE WEARING THAT
TO IMPRESS THE WOMEN ON RISA,
YOU MAY AS WELL STAY ON BOARD.
RULE NUMBER ONE--YOU'VE GOT TO
BE SEEN TO GET NOTICED.
AND I PLAN ON GETTING NOTICED.
ARCHER: DON'T SAY
SHE DIDN'T WARN YOU.
FIGURE OUT YOUR ITINERARY YET?
ARCHER: I THINK I'M GONNA PASS.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN, YOU NEED THIS
AS MUCH AS I DO.
ARCHER: NOBODY
NEEDS THIS AS MUCH AS YOU DO.
[TUCKER CHUCKLES]
ARCHER: THE SHIP WILL
BE NICE AND QUIET.
I'VE GOT
SOME ASTROMETRIC SURVEYS
THAT HAVE BEEN PILING UP.
IT'LL BE A GOOD CHANCE
TO GET SOME WORK DONE.
WE'RE GOING TO A PLANET
WITH OVER 200 REGISTERED
NUVIAN MASSEUSES
AND YOU'RE GONNA SIT
IN YOUR CABIN
WITH A BUNCH OF STAR CHARTS?
MR. TUCKER HAS A POINT.
ARCHER: YOU THINK
I NEED A MASSAGE?
T'POL: THE SAFETY OF THIS SHIP
DEPENDS ON ITS CAPTAIN
BEING AT HIS MOST EFFICIENT.
I SUPPOSE I COULD READ
THOSE SURVEYS ON A NICE BEACH.
T'POL: INCOMING TRANSMISSION
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND.
TRANSFER IT TO MY READY ROOM.
HER NAME'S V'LAR.
SHE'S THE VULCAN AMBASSADOR
TO A PLANET CALLED MAZAR.
IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY ASKING, ADMIRAL,
WHY IS THIS OUR PROBLEM?
APPARENTLY, IT'S IMPERATIVE
THAT SHE BE TAKEN OFF THAT
PLANET AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
THE NEAREST VULCAN SHIP
IS AT LEAST A WEEK AWAY.
DO THEY EXPECT US TO TAKE HER
ALL THE WAY BACK TO VULCAN?
YOU'LL RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE VULCAN SHIP SH'RAAN
IN 3 DAYS.
THEY'LL TAKE HER
THE REST OF THE WAY.
ANY IDEA WHAT THE EMERGENCY IS?
WELL, THIS MAY COME AS A SHOCK
TO YOU, JON,
BUT THE VULCANS AREN'T TALKING.
IMAGINE THAT.
T'POL: THANK YOU
FOR VOLUNTEERING YOUR QUARTERS.
HOSHI: I'M HAPPY TO DO IT.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD
TO MEETING HER.
T'POL: I IMAGINE SHE'LL SPEND
MOST OF THE JOURNEY ALONE,
ENGAGED IN MEDITATION.
BUT IF IT SEEMS APPROPRIATE,
I'LL ASK
IF SHE'LL MEET WITH YOU.
HOSHI: THANKS.
WELL, IF THERE'S
ANYTHING ELSE I CAN DO...
T'POL: IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND
TAKING THAT.
AMBASSADOR V'LAR IS ACCUSTOMED
TO A SPARTAN ENVIRONMENT.
ARCHER: HOSHI.
THANKS FOR GIVING UP YOUR CABIN.
HOSHI: JUST HOPE
IT'S SPARTAN ENOUGH, SIR.
ARCHER: EVERYTHING SET?
T'POL: I BELIEVE SO.
I'VE PREPARED THIS
TO FAMILIARIZE THE CREW
WITH THE NECESSARY PROTOCOLS.
WE SHOULD ASSIGN A STEWARD
TO ATTEND TO HER NEEDS.
"DON'T ADDRESS THE AMBASSADOR
UNLESS SPOKEN TO FIRST.
"DON'T OFFER TO SHAKE HANDS.
REFRAIN FROM LAUGHING
IN HER PRESENCE."
T'POL: THOSE GUIDELINES
ARE LARGELY PRECAUTIONARY.
I DOUBT THE CREW
WILL HAVE MUCH OPPORTUNITY
TO INTERACT WITH HER.
YOU SEEM TO BE
PULLING OUT ALL THE STOPS.
I'M SIMPLY FOLLOWING
THE PROTOCOLS
USED IN DEALING
WITH AN AMBASSADOR
OF V'LAR'S DISTINCTION.
WELL, SHE'LL BE HERE
SOON ENOUGH.
LET ME KNOW IF YOU NEED
ANY HELP.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
[SNIFFS]
TRAVIS: ENTERING ORBIT, SIR.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI: WE'RE BEING HAILED.
IT'S THE MAZARITE HIGH COUNCIL.
ARCHER: SOMEONE'S IN A HURRY.
CAPTAIN ARCHER?
ARCHER: I'M JONATHAN ARCHER.
ARE YOU PREPARED TO RECEIVE
AMBASSADOR V'LAR?
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
IF YOU'LL TRANSMIT
YOUR LANDING COORDINATES TO US,
WE'LL SEND DOWN A SHUTTLEPOD.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD
TO THE VISIT.
I REGRET THERE WON'T BE TIME
FOR THAT.
THE AMBASSADOR IS ALREADY
ON HER WAY TO YOUR SHIP.
A SMALL CRAFT'S
APPROACHING, SIR.
I ASSUME THE VULCANS
HAVE INFORMED YOU
OF THE URGENCY OF THIS MATTER.
ARCHER: THEY SAID
IT WAS IMPORTANT
THAT WE PICK UP THE AMBASSADOR
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
THEY DIDN'T SAY WHY.
V'LAR HAS BEEN EXPELLED
FOR ABUSE OF HER POSITION
AND CRIMINAL MISCONDUCT.
CAPTAIN ARCHER?
ARCHER: AMBASSADOR.
ON BEHALF OF MY CREW,
I'D LIKE TO WELCOME YOU
ABOARD "ENTERPRISE."
V'LAR: THANK YOU.
MAY I TAKE THAT?
V'LAR: THAT'S VERY THOUGHTFUL,
CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: THIS IS COMMANDER
CHARLES TUCKER,
MY CHIEF ENGINEER.
TUCKER: PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
V'LAR: THE PLEASURE IS MINE,
COMMANDER.
ARCHER: AND THIS IS
MY SCIENCE OFFICER,
SUBCOMMANDER T'POL.
[T'POL AND V'LAR
SPEAKING VULCAN]
BUT PLEASE. I'VE BEEN
ANTICIPATING THE OPPORTUNITY
TO PRACTICE MY ENGLISH.
I HOPE YOU LIKE
YOUR QUARTERS, AMBASSADOR.
T'POL TRIED VERY HARD
TO ANTICIPATE YOUR NEEDS.
FORTUNATELY,
MY NEEDS ARE FEW, CAPTAIN.
I AM CURIOUS, THOUGH--
WHO PREVIOUSLY OCCUPIED
THE CABIN?
T'POL: THE ODOR.
THE HUMAN SCENT
IS DIFFICULT TO MASK.
V'LAR: ACTUALLY, I WAS
HOPING TO MEET THE CREW MEMBER,
IN ORDER TO THANK HER
FOR ALLOWING ME
TO DISRUPT HER ROUTINE.
I PREFER NOT TO INCONVENIENCE
ANYONE IF POSSIBLE.
THAT PHILOSOPHY HAS SERVED ME
WELL IN THE DIPLOMATIC SERVICE.
T'POL TELLS ME YOU NEGOTIATED
THE FIRST TERRITORIAL ACCORDS
BETWEEN VULCAN AND ANDORIA.
THE ANDORIANS REQUIRED
A SOMEWHAT FIRMER HAND
AT THE NEGOTIATING TABLE.
BUT I WAS YOUNGER THEN.
THAT WAS BEFORE WE EVEN
MADE CONTACT WITH EARTH.
THAT WAS OVER 90 YEARS AGO.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
A DIPLOMAT?
COMMANDER TUCKER.
I UNDERSTOOD THAT ON YOUR WORLD
IT IS CONSIDERED BAD MANNERS
TO ASK A LADY HER AGE.
WELL, I-I WASN'T, UM...
I, UH...
DIDN'T MEAN TO IMPLY
THAT YOU WERE...
V'LAR: FORGIVE ME, COMMANDER.
MY ATTEMPT AT HUMOR.
V'LAR: SUFFICE IT TO SAY,
THAT WITH T'POL AND MYSELF HERE,
YOU'RE ALMOST CERTAINLY DINING
WITH THE TWO OLDEST PEOPLE
ON THIS SHIP.
I HOPE, AMBASSADOR,
THAT YOU REGARD THE CHARGES
AGAINST YOU WITH LESS LEVITY.
OF COURSE I DO.
HOW DO YOU INTEND
TO DEFEND YOURSELF?
THERE IS NO DEFENSE.
ARE YOU SAYING YOU'RE GUILTY?
ARCHER: T'POL.
V'LAR: IT'S ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
A PERSON IN MY POSITION CARRIES
THE TRUST OF ALL VULCANS.
THE FACT THAT THE MAZARITES
BELIEVE THAT TRUST
HAS BEEN COMPROMISED
JUSTIFIES T'POL'S CONCERN.
I'M AFRAID MY AGE
IS BETRAYING ME, CAPTAIN.
WOULD YOU MIND IF I RETIRED?
ARCHER: OF COURSE NOT.
I'VE NEVER BEEN TO EARTH.
BUT I FIND THE HUMANS I HAVE
ENCOUNTERED QUITE UNPREDICTABLE.
I'D BE INTERESTED IN HEARING
ABOUT YOUR EXPERIENCES THERE.
T'POL: ANOTHER TIME PERHAPS.
V'LAR: I UNDERSTAND.
T'POL: THIS IS YOUR CABIN.
I'LL SAY GOOD NIGHT.
V'LAR: T'POL.
I SENSE YOUR ANGER.
T'POL: YOU PRESUME
THAT MY TIME WITH HUMANS
HAS LEFT ME SUSCEPTIBLE
TO THEIR EMOTIONS.
V'LAR: THEY'RE OUR
EMOTIONS AS WELL.
WE SIMPLY HIDE THEM BETTER.
T'POL: IF YOU'RE
SENSING ANYTHING FROM ME,
IT ISN'T ANGER.
V'LAR: NO.
DISAPPOINTMENT.
T'POL: GOOD NIGHT, AMBASSADOR.
ARCHER: T'POL.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: IS THERE A PROBLEM
I SHOULD BE AWARE OF?
T'POL: I ASSUME YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT AMBASSADOR V'LAR.
ARCHER: YOU WERE A BIT
ABRUPT WITH HER.
T'POL: IF YOU BELIEVE I WAS
RUDE, I'LL CONVEY MY APOLOGIES.
ARCHER: I DON'T PRETEND
TO UNDERSTAND VULCANS.
I NEVER HAVE.
BUT I WOULDN'T BE A VERY GOOD
CAPTAIN IF I DIDN'T KNOW
WHEN SOMETHING WAS BOTHERING
MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
T'POL: IT'S UNCOMMON FOR
A VULCAN TO COMMIT A CRIME.
ARCHER: UNCOMMON,
BUT NOT UNHEARD OF.
T'POL: UNHEARD OF FOR A PERSON
IN AMBASSADOR V'LAR'S POSITION.
ARCHER: WE DON'T
KNOW WHAT SHE'S DONE.
T'POL: IT DOESN'T MATTER.
IF SHE WERE INNOCENT,
SHE WOULD HAVE INSISTED
ON STAYING TO DEFEND HERSELF.
ARCHER: YOU SEEM TO KNOW
A LOT ABOUT HER.
T'POL: I'VE MET
THE AMBASSADOR BEFORE,
THOUGH SHE CLEARLY
DOESN'T RECALL.
IT WAS MANY YEARS AGO ON VULCAN
DURING MY EARLY SCHOOLING.
SHE HAD JUST NEGOTIATED
THE TREATY OF KA'TANN
AND I TRAVELED
A GREAT DISTANCE TO SEE HER.
ARCHER: WAS IT WORTH THE TRIP?
T'POL: THE AMBASSADOR
INSPIRED ME
TO CHOOSE A DIRECTION
IN MY OWN LIFE,
A PATH THAT LED ME
TO THE SCIENCE COUNCIL
AND EVENTUALLY HERE.
ARCHER: I'VE HAD A FEW
HEROES IN MY LIFE.
IT'S NEVER EASY
WHEN ONE OF THEM LETS YOU DOWN.
T'POL: VULCANS
DON'T HAVE HEROES.
ARCHER: NO.
I'M SURE THEY DON'T.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
REED: CAPTAIN, CAN YOU
COME TO THE BRIDGE?
ARCHER: ON MY WAY.
TRAVIS: AN UNIDENTIFIED
VESSEL, SIR,
50,000 KILOMETERS AND CLOSING.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI: THEY'RE HAILING US.
ARCHER:
LET'S FIND OUT WHO THEY ARE.
WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU?
MY APOLOGIES, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S BEEN A CHANGE OF PLANS
REGARDING AMBASSADOR V'LAR.
WE WEREN'T TOLD.
WE'VE BEEN HAVING SOME PROBLEMS
WITH OUR LONG-RANGE
COMMUNICATIONS.
WHAT'S THE CHANGE OF PLANS?
THE MAGISTRATE FEELS THAT
WE LET THE AMBASSADOR
GO TOO QUICKLY.
SHE'S NEEDED
FOR ADDITIONAL QUESTIONING.
WE DON'T WANT TO CAUSE YOU
ANY MORE INCONVENIENCE.
IF YOU'LL DROP OUT OF WARP,
WE CAN DOCK WITH YOU
AND TAKE THE AMBASSADOR
ABOARD OUR SHIP.
YOUR MAGISTRATE SEEMED IN
A BIG HURRY TO GET RID OF HER.
NOW HE WANTS HER BACK?
[CHUCKLES]
I'M JUST A TRANSPORT CAPTAIN.
I NEVER TRY TO MAKE SENSE
OF WHAT GOVERNMENT BUREAUCRATS
ARE THINKING.
I'LL HAVE TO CONTACT
MY SUPERIORS.
THERE'S REALLY NO NEED.
I'M JUST A STARSHIP CAPTAIN.
YOU DON'T THINK THEY'D TRUST ME
TO MAKE THESE KINDS OF DECISIONS
ON MY OWN?
WE'LL WAIT FOR YOU TO CONFIRM
WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO.
GET ME STARFLEET COMMAND.
HOSHI: I CAN'T GET THROUGH.
THAT SHIP'S JAMMING
ALL OUR COM FREQUENCIES.
ARCHER:
"JUST A TRANSPORT CAPTAIN."
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
ARCHER:
POLARIZE THE HULL PLATING.
ARCHER: WHAT THE HELL
IS HE DOING? HAIL HIM.
HOSHI: HE'S NOT ANSWERING.
PORT HULL PLATING'S OFF-LINE.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE CLOSING.
FAST.
AFT TORPEDOES.
RETURN FIRE.
REED: NO EFFECT.
THEY'RE USING SOME KIND
OF ENERGY SHIELDING.
T'POL: DIRECT HIT
TO ENGINEERING, SUBSECTION 12.
WE'VE TAKEN DAMAGE.
WOULD THE PHASE CANNONS
BE MORE EFFECTIVE?
REED: UNDOUBTEDLY.
BUT WE CAN'T FIRE THEM AT WARP.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU MEAN
WE CAN'T FIRE THEM AT WARP?
REED: PARTICLE DISCHARGE, SIR.
IT WOULD DESTABILIZE
OUR WARP FIELD
AND MOST LIKELY
BLOW OUT BOTH NACELLES.
I'VE BEEN WORKING ON THE
PROBLEM, BUT I HAVEN'T QUITE--
[ALARM]
DROP TO IMPULSE.
DEPLOY THE AFT CANNON.
REED: I'VE GOT A LOCK.
ARCHER: FIRE.
THEIR SHIELDS ARE FAILING.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN DO
ABOUT THEIR ENGINES.
THEY'RE DEAD IN THE WATER, SIR.
HOSHI: NOT DEAD ENOUGH.
ARCHER: RESUME COURSE, WARP 4.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
ANY IDEA WHAT THAT
WAS ALL ABOUT?
WELL, I THINK WE KNOW
SOMEONE WHO MIGHT.
ARCHER: WE WERE
ASKED TO PICK YOU UP
AND DELIVER YOU
TO A VULCAN SHIP.
NO ONE SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT GETTING SHOT AT.
T'POL: YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHO THEY WERE?
V'LAR: OBVIOUSLY THEY WEREN'T
SENT BY THE COUNCIL ON MAZAR.
ARCHER: THEN WHO SENT THEM?
I HAVE NO ANSWERS FOR YOU.
AMBASSADOR...
WE'RE HERE AT THE REQUEST
OF THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND.
IT WOULD BE ILLOGICAL FOR YOU
TO WITHHOLD INFORMATION FROM US.
THERE ARE DIPLOMATIC MATTERS
AT STAKE HERE
WHICH DO NOT CONCERN YOU.
TO TELL YOU ANY MORE
WOULD ONLY PUT YOUR SHIP
AND YOUR CREW AT GREATER RISK.
ARCHER:
HOW MUCH GREATER COULD IT GET?
A FEW MORE VOLLEYS
FROM THAT SHIP
WOULD HAVE RUPTURED OUR HULL.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: SO AM I.
YOU'RE LEAVING ME
NO CHOICE, AMBASSADOR.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO MAYWEATHER.
TRAVIS: GO AHEAD.
CHANGE OF PLANS, TRAVIS.
LAY IN A COURSE BACK TO MAZAR.
TRAVIS: SIR?
ARCHER: YOU HEARD ME.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
YOU'RE UNDER STRICT ORDERS TO
TRANSPORT ME TO THE "SH'RAAN."
IT'S MORE THAN TWO DAYS
TO THE RENDEZVOUS POINT,
AND THERE COULD BE OTHER
HOSTILE SHIPS TRACKING US.
UNLESS YOU CAN CONVINCE ME
WHY IT'S WORTH
RISKING ALL OUR LIVES...
THE VULCANS ARE RAISING
HOLY HELL ABOUT THIS, JON.
YOU COULD ALWAYS ORDER ME
TO TAKE HER
TO THE RENDEZVOUS POINT.
YOU'RE OUT THERE.
I'M NOT. IT'S YOUR CALL.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
THERE'LL BE REPERCUSSIONS.
THEY CERTAINLY CONSIDERED
THE REPERCUSSIONS.
THEY KNEW SOMEONE WAS AFTER HER.
WHY RISK ONE OF YOUR OWN SHIPS
WHEN YOU CAN RISK ONE OF OURS?
JON...
THEY'RE DOING IT
TO US AGAIN, ADMIRAL!
KEEPING US IN THE DARK.
HAVE YOU TALKED
TO THE AMBASSADOR?
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
I'VE TRIED.
WELL, MAYBE SHE BROUGHT THIS
ON HERSELF.
YOU DID SAY THAT SHE ADMITTED
THE CHARGES AGAINST HER
WERE TRUE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT
THE CHARGES AGAINST HER ARE.
WELL, I'LL TALK TO SOVAL,
SEE WHAT I CAN FIND OUT.
TUCKER: YOU REALLY ENJOY THIS,
DON'T YOU?
REED: REPLACING POWER COUPLINGS?
HARDLY.
TUCKER: NO, I MEAN HAVING
PEOPLE SHOOT AT US.
REED: IF YOU MUST KNOW, I MUCH
PREFER THE SHOOTING-BACK PART.
TUCKER: I THOUGHT THIS MISSION
WAS ABOUT PEACEFUL EXPLORATION.
REED: I NEED SOMETHING
TO DO ON THIS SHIP, COMMANDER.
TUCKER: FAIR ENOUGH.
I'M JUST HOPING WE DON'T
KEEP YOU QUITE SO BUSY.
I READ THOSE NUVIAN MASSEUSES
HAVE 12 FINGERS...
ON EACH HAND.
REED: THEN I'D SAY STARFLEET
NEEDS TO MAKE
ITS PRESENCE KNOWN ON RISA.
TUCKER: MM-HMM.
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
T'POL: I HOPE I'M
NOT INTERRUPTING.
V'LAR: NOT AT ALL.
HOSHI: WE WERE JUST TALKING
ABOUT MY QUARTERS.
V'LAR: I WAS WONDERING WHY
THEY WERE SO SPARSELY DECORATED.
IF YOU NEED ANYTHING,
IT CAN BE BROUGHT TO YOU.
V'LAR: OH, I DON'T WANT
TO BE WAITED ON.
AND SINCE I DOUBT I'LL BE
TRAVELING TO EARTH ANYTIME SOON,
I DECIDED TO SPEND
A LITTLE TIME WITH MY HOSTS.
THANK YOU FOR
THE USE OF YOUR QUARTERS.
YOU'LL HAVE THEM BACK
SOON ENOUGH.
[HOSHI AND V'LAR
SPEAKING VULCAN]
HOSHI: SUBCOMMANDER.
V'LAR HAVE YOU TRIED ICED TEA?
T'POL: I DON'T CARE FOR IT.
V'LAR:
CAPTAIN ARCHER CERTAINLY DOES.
IT'S FLAVORED
WITH PASSION FRUIT.
AN APPROPRIATE INGREDIENT
FOR HIM, DON'T YOU THINK?
T'POL: IT WAS THE CAPTAIN THAT
I WANTED TO SPEAK TO YOU ABOUT.
V'LAR:
HE'S A MOST INTRIGUING MAN.
T'POL: HE DESERVES TO BE TOLD
THE TRUTH.
V'LAR: WILL YOU JOIN ME?
PLEASE.
WE'LL BE BACK AT MAZAR
IN A FEW HOURS.
I'D PREFER NOT TO WASTE
THAT TIME ALONE.
V'LAR: THIS MUST
BE AWKWARD FOR YOU,
HAVING A FOOT IN TWO WORLDS--
LOYAL TO YOUR CAPTAIN,
YET STILL A VULCAN.
T'POL: YOU CAN MAKE THINGS
EASIER FOR HIM.
THE HIGH COMMAND HAS
REQUESTED HIS ASSISTANCE.
IT DOESN'T SEEM UNREASONABLE
TO ASK WHY.
YOU BELIEVE CAPTAIN ARCHER
CAN BE TRUSTED.
YES.
EVEN THOUGH HE CLEARLY
DOESN'T TRUST US?
HE'S RESENTFUL.
V'LAR: WHY?
T'POL: HE BELIEVES WE HELD BACK
THEIR DEVELOPMENT
OF WARP TECHNOLOGY.
V'LAR: WE'VE KEPT MANY THINGS
FROM THEM, ALL FOR GOOD REASON.
T'POL: BUT SITUATIONS LIKE THIS
ONLY REINFORCE THEIR RESENTMENT.
IF WE EXPECT TO CONTINUE
OUR RELATIONS WITH HUMANITY,
WE HAVE TO EARN THEIR TRUST.
V'LAR: I WOULD NOT
HAVE SUCCEEDED AT MY CAREER
FOR 94 YEARS WITHOUT
EARNING PEOPLE'S TRUST.
T'POL: I MEANT NO INSULT.
V'LAR: OF COURSE NOT.
YOU WERE SIMPLY
SPEAKING YOUR MIND.
AS YOU ALWAYS HAVE.
IT WAS AT VULCANA REGAR,
WASN'T IT?
DURING THE SECOND
KA'TANN CONFERENCE.
YOU APPROACHED ME
DURING A RECESS.
YOU REMEMBER.
YOU WERE NOT EASY TO FORGET.
YOUR QUESTIONS ABOUT
MY NEGOTIATING TACTICS
WERE QUITE PRESUMPTUOUS
COMING FROM ONE SO YOUNG.
I APOLOGIZE
IF I ACTED INAPPROPRIATELY.
NOT AT ALL.
IN FACT, YOUR BLUNTNESS
MADE ME RECONSIDER
SOME OF MY POSITIONS.
MUCH AS IT HAS NOW.
T'POL...
I HAVE SOMETHING TO TELL YOU.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
ARCHER: SOMETHING WRONG?
T'POL: I TOOK THE LIBERTY OF
SPEAKING WITH AMBASSADOR V'LAR.
ARCHER: GO ON.
ANY LUCK?
T'POL: THE AMBASSADOR AND I
SPENT THE LAST
TWO HOURS TALKING.
SHE'S EVEN MORE REMARKABLE
THAN HER REPUTATION SUGGESTS.
ARCHER: I DON'T DOUBT THAT.
BUT IT DOESN'T AFFECT
MY DECISION.
T'POL: I BELIEVE IT SHOULD.
SHE'S NOT GUILTY OF THE CRIME
SHE'S BEEN ACCUSED OF.
SHE TOLD YOU THAT?
T'POL: THE CHARGES WERE
FABRICATED TO GET HER OFF MAZAR
AND DIVERT ATTENTION
FROM HER ACTUAL MISSION.
ARCHER: WHICH IS?
T'POL: SHE CAN'T REVEAL THAT.
[SIGHS]
BUT SHE'S CONVINCED ME
THAT IT'S CRITICAL
WE HELP HER ACCOMPLISH IT.
I'M SORRY, T'POL,
BUT I'M GONNA NEED
MORE THAN THAT.
SHE ALSO TOLD ME THAT
IF WE RETURN HER TO MAZAR,
SHE'LL BE KILLED.
BY WHO?
T'POL: SHE WOULDN'T TELL ME.
ARCHER: BUT YOU BELIEVED HER?
T'POL: YES.
ARCHER: WHY?
T'POL: I CAN'T ACCEPT
THAT SHE'D SACRIFICE
A LIFETIME OF ACCOMPLISHMENTS
WITH AN ACT
OF CRIMINAL MISCONDUCT.
IT HAPPENS ALL THE TIME.
T'POL: NOT TO HER.
WE MUST TAKE HER TO THE SH'RAAN.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO PUT THE LIVES OF
EVERYONE ON BOARD IN JEOPARDY
BASED ON YOUR TALKING TO THIS
WOMAN FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS?
CAPTAIN...
SINCE I'VE SERVED
ABOARD "ENTERPRISE,"
I'VE NEVER ASKED YOU
FOR ANYTHING.
I'M ASKING FOR THIS NOW.
DON'T RETURN
THE AMBASSADOR TO MAZAR.
PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
REED: OUR MAZARITE FRIEND, SIR.
AND HE BROUGHT COMPANY.
ARCHER: WHY DIDN'T
WE SEE THEM COMING?
OUR AFT SENSORS
ARE STILL OUT OF ALIGNMENT.
THEY'RE TARGETING OUR ENGINES.
REED: WE COULD DROP TO IMPULSE,
USE THE PHASE CANNONS.
AND GO 3 AGAINST ONE?
ARCHER: YOU'RE FAMILIAR
WITH THE MAZARITES.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THEIR TOP SPEED?
T'POL: COMPARABLE TO STARFLEET.
I DON'T BELIEVE
THEY'VE EXCEEDED WARP 5.
THEN LET'S GIVE THEM
A RUN FOR THEIR MONEY.
TRAVIS, INCREASE SPEED
TO WARP 4.8.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
TRAVIS: WARP 4.8.
THEY'RE MATCHING OUR SPEED
AND ACCELERATING. WARP 4.9.
THEY'RE CLOSING.
TO 20,000 KILOMETERS.
15.
ARCHER: TRAVIS.
TRAVIS: WARP 4.9.
THEY'RE HOLDING AT 4.9, SIR.
ARCHER: HOW FAR TO
THE RENDEZVOUS POINT?
TRAVIS: AT THIS SPEED,
A LITTLE OVER TWO HOURS.
BUT I DON'T THINK WE CAN
HOLD IT THAT LONG.
ARCHER: CAN WE GET A MESSAGE
THROUGH TO THE VULCANS?
THE MAZARITES
ARE STILL JAMMING US.
KEEP TRYING.
THAT VULCAN SHIP
BETTER NOT BE LATE.
V'LAR: CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S OUR SITUATION?
WE'RE BEING CHASED
BY 3 MAZARITE SHIPS.
WILL WE REACH THE SH'RAAN
BEFORE THEY CAN DO
ANY MORE DAMAGE?
ARCHER: I'M NOT SURE.
IN THAT CASE,
I NEED TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
I HAVE TO CONSIDER
THE POSSIBILITY
THAT THIS MISSION WILL FAIL.
YOU STILL HAVEN'T TOLD ME
WHAT THIS MISSION IS.
I'VE BEEN UNDER ORDERS TO TELL
YOU ONLY WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW.
BUT THAT WASN'T THE ONLY REASON
I KEPT THINGS FROM YOU.
I DIDN'T TRUST YOU.
AS YOUR MR. TUCKER POINTED OUT,
I HAVE BEEN AROUND A LONG TIME.
I REMEMBER WHEN NEWS OF YOUR
PEOPLE FIRST REACHED VULCAN.
I WAS FASCINATED BY HUMANITY
BUT WORRIED AS WELL.
ARCHER: YOU HADN'T EVEN MET US.
V'LAR: YOU HAD JUST EMERGED
FROM A GLOBAL WAR.
THE IDEA THAT YOU
DEEMED YOURSELVES READY
TO JOIN THE INTERSTELLAR
COMMUNITY SEEMED...
PREMATURE.
AND A CENTURY OF GOOD BEHAVIOR
HASN'T CHANGED YOUR MIND?
THE MAZARITES PURSUING US
ARE CRIMINALS.
THEY ARE
MEMBERS OF AN ORGANIZATION
THAT'S INFILTRATED
ALL LEVELS OF GOVERNMENT,
MAKING THEMSELVES
WEALTHY AND POWERFUL
AT THE EXPENSE
OF MANY INNOCENT VICTIMS.
THEIR METHODS INCLUDE
ELIMINATING ANYONE
WHO STANDS IN THEIR WAY.
ARCHER:
AND THAT WOULD INCLUDE YOU.
MANY MAZARITES
WANT THEIR GOVERNMENT
PURGED OF THIS CORRUPTION.
THEY ASKED THE VULCAN CONSULATE
TO HELP THEM EXPOSE
THESE CRIMINALS.
AND THAT JOB FELL TO YOU?
I HAVE BEEN GATHERING EVIDENCE
AGAINST THEM.
IN 3 MONTHS,
I WILL BE CALLED TO TESTIFY.
IT WAS DECIDED THAT UNTIL THEN
I WOULD BE SAFER ON VULCAN.
WHY COULDN'T YOU TELL US?
THE INVESTIGATION WAS
CONSIDERED TOO SENSITIVE.
AND THE STORY OF YOU
BEING RECALLED IN DISGRACE?
IT WAS HOPED THAT
IF MY REPUTATION WERE SULLIED,
THEY WOULD NOT CONSIDER ME
A CREDIBLE WITNESS
AND THEY MIGHT NOT
COME AFTER ME.
OBVIOUSLY, IT DIDN'T WORK.
THE CORRUPTION RAN
DEEPER THAN I THOUGHT.
I APPRECIATE...
YOU TELLING ME THE TRUTH.
I CAN NO LONGER PUT YOU AND
YOUR CREW IN DANGER, CAPTAIN.
PLEASE DROP OUT OF WARP.
I PLAN TO SURRENDER MYSELF
TO THEM.
IT HASN'T GOTTEN TO THAT YET.
V'LAR: IT'S THE MOST LOGICAL
COURSE OF ACTION.
ARCHER: IF YOU'VE LEARNED
ANYTHING ABOUT HUMANS,
YOU'D KNOW
WE DON'T ALWAYS TAKE THE MOST
LOGICAL COURSE OF ACTION.
[BEEPS]
T'POL: CAPTAIN,
REPORT TO THE BRIDGE.
THEY'RE HAILING US.
ARCHER: WHAT'S OUR STATUS?
T'POL: HOLDING AT WARP 4.9.
BUT COMMANDER TUCKER DOESN'T
BELIEVE WE CAN SUSTAIN IT
FOR MORE
THAN ANOTHER 10 MINUTES.
REED: I DON'T BELIEVE
THEY CAN EITHER, SIR.
THEY'RE RELEASING DRIVE PLASMA
TO KEEP THEIR WARP COILS
FROM OVERLOADING.
ARCHER: OPEN A CHANNEL.
CAPTAIN. AMBASSADOR.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU WANT?
JUST GIVING YOU
A FRIENDLY WARNING.
ARE YOU AWARE THAT
YOUR ENGINES ARE OVERHEATING?
ARCHER: SO ARE YOURS.
WE HAVE NO QUARREL WITH YOU.
GIVE US THE VULCAN
AND YOU'LL BE FREE TO GO.
ARCHER: I HAVE A BETTER IDEA.
WHY DON'T YOU SLOW DOWN
BEFORE YOUR ENGINES EXPLODE?
WHY WOULD YOU RISK THE LIVES
OF YOUR CREW FOR THIS CRIMINAL?
ARCHER: I'VE BEEN ORDERED
TO DELIVER HER
SAFELY TO THE VULCANS.
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I PLAN TO DO.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE
INCREASING SPEED.
WARP 4.95.
THEY'RE REENTERING
WEAPONS RANGE, SIR.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
PLEASE TELL ME
YOU'RE READY TO SLOW DOWN.
ARCHER: SORRY, TRIP,
BUT WE NEED A LITTLE MORE SPEED.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH MORE
I CAN GIVE YOU.
IT'S CALLED A WARP 5 ENGINE.
TUCKER: ON PAPER.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY CHOICE, TRIP.
AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: AMBASSADOR.
WARP 5.
4.93.
0.95.
[ALARM]
DON'T TAKE YOUR EYES
OFF THAT ANTIMATTER STREAM.
CREWWOMAN: YES, SIR.
TRAVIS: 4.97.
REED: THEY'RE
MATCHING OUR SPEED.
4.99.
WARP 5.
REED: THEY'RE
STILL GAINING ON US.
ARCHER: HOW FAR
TO THE VULCAN SHIP?
THEIR JAMMING SIGNAL IS
DISRUPTING OUR SENSORS AS WELL.
ARCHER: THEN USE
THEIR LAST-KNOWN POSITION
AND DO THE MATH.
TAKE A GUESS.
T'POL: IF WE COULD MAINTAIN
OUR PRESENT SPEED,
APPROXIMATELY 53 MINUTES.
REED: THE MAZARITES WILL BE IN
FIRING RANGE LONG BEFORE THEN.
ARCHER: WHAT IF WE COULD
GET A MESSAGE THROUGH--
TELL THEM TO GET HERE
AS FAST AS THEY CAN?
T'POL: THE SH'RAAN IS
CAPABLE OF WARP 7.
IF WE COULD MAINTAIN WARP 5,
WE'D REACH THEM IN 12 MINUTES.
ARCHER: HOSHI, ANY WAY
YOU CAN GET A MESSAGE
THROUGH THE INTERFERENCE?
HOSHI: I DON'T SEE HOW, SIR.
V'LAR: THERE'S A DIPLOMATIC
FREQUENCY WE SOMETIMES USE.
IT'S IN A LOWER SUBSPACE BAND.
I DOUBT THE MAZARITES
ARE AWARE OF IT.
IT'S BEEN A FEW YEARS
SINCE I DID THIS.
IF WE DO GET A MESSAGE
THROUGH TO THE VULCANS,
WE DON'T WANT THE MAZARITES
TO SEE THEM COMING.
REED: WE COULD TRY DEFLECTING
THEIR JAMMING SIGNAL, SIR.
USE IT TO BLIND
THEIR SENSORS AS WELL.
ARCHER: SEE WHAT YOU CAN DO.
REED: AYE, SIR.
V'LAR: YES. YES.
HOSHI?
HOSHI: WE MAY HAVE GOTTEN
A MESSAGE THROUGH TO THEM, SIR,
BUT I'M NOT SURE.
T'POL: WOULDN'T THEY RESPOND?
TUCKER: TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE!
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
TUCKER: THE PORT INJECTORS
JUST BLEW!
WE'VE GOT TO SLOW DOWN, CAPTAIN!
CREWMAN: I GOT IT!
I GOT IT!
ARCHER: HOSHI.
HOSHI:
THE COM JUST WENT DOWN, SIR.
THEY'RE RIGHT ON TOP OF US.
ARCHER: HOW LONG?
T'POL: 8 MINUTES.
THAT'S A DIRECT HIT
TO OUR STARBOARD NACELLE.
TRAVIS:
WE'RE DROPPING TO IMPULSE.
[BEEP]
HOSHI: THEY'RE HAILING US.
ARCHER: HOW LONG NOW?
T'POL: IF THEY RECEIVED OUR
MESSAGE, ANOTHER 10 MINUTES.
ARCHER: BUT IT WAS DOWN TO 8.
T'POL: THAT WAS BEFORE
WE DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
REED: WE CAN'T HOLD OFF
THOSE SHIPS FOR THAT LONG.
V'LAR: YOU'VE DONE YOUR BEST,
CAPTAIN, AND I THANK YOU FOR IT.
BUT IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO TURN MYSELF OVER TO THEM.
ARCHER: WE JUST NEED TO BUY
10 MORE MINUTES.
V'LAR: CAPTAIN...
ARCHER: I WANT YOU
TO GO TO SICK BAY.
V'LAR: SICK BAY?
ARCHER: I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
IF THERE WAS EVER A TIME
TO START TRUSTING US,
THIS WOULD BE IT.
PUT HIM THROUGH.
GIVE US THE VULCAN.
YOU KNOW, I HONESTLY DIDN'T
THINK YOU'D BE ABLE TO CATCH US.
JUST OUT OF CURIOSITY,
HOW FAST DO YOUR SHIPS GO?
PUT HER ON A SHUTTLE AND BRING
HER TO OUR LEAD VESSEL.
ARCHER: THAT COULD BE A PROBLEM.
OUR SHUTTLE BAY WAS DAMAGED,
THANKS TO YOU.
I DOUBT WE COULD LAUNCH
A SHUTTLEPOD
UNTIL IT'S REPAIRED.
WHAT...
WHAT WOULD
YOU HAVE TOPPED OUT AT?
WARP 5.5? WARP 6?
I CAN'T IMAGINE YOU COULD DO
MUCH MORE THAN THAT.
IT SEEMED LIKE YOUR ENGINES
WERE STARTING TO RUN PRETTY HOT.
PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
MALCOLM, I'M COUNTING ON YOU.
ARCHER: T'POL.
ARCHER: OK.
CAPTAIN: WHERE IS SHE?
ARCHER: YOUR LAST ATTACK
BLEW OUT
SYSTEMS ACROSS HALF THE SHIP.
POWER'S DOWN IN ENGINEERING.
A PLASMA CONDUIT
EXPLODED ON "E" DECK.
CAPTAIN: I DIDN'T ASK
FOR A DAMAGE REPORT.
WHERE IS SHE?
ARCHER: I WAS GETTING TO THAT.
HER QUARTERS ARE ON "E" DECK.
SHE WAS NO MORE THAN 10 METERS
AWAY WHEN THE CONDUIT BLEW.
T'POL: HER INJURIES
ARE EXTENSIVE.
PLASMA BURNS,
NEUROLOGICAL TRAUMA.
CAPTAIN: I WANT TO SEE HER.
ARCHER: THIS IS DR. PHLOX.
CAPTAIN: THE VULCAN?
PHLOX: SHE'S UNDERGOING
DERMAL REGENERATION.
CAPTAIN: OPEN IT.
PHLOX: I WILL NOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT BUSINESS
YOU HAVE WITH THIS WOMAN,
BUT WHEN SHE WAS BROUGHT
IN HERE, SHE BECAME MY PATIENT.
IF I REMOVE HER FROM THE IMAGING
CHAMBER PREMATURELY, SHE'LL DIE.
CAPTAIN: OPEN IT.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
YES?
MAZARITE: OUR SENSORS
JUST WENT DOWN, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN: WHAT'S CAUSING IT?
MAZARITE: "ENTERPRISE" IS
REDIRECTING OUR JAMMING SIGNAL.
PHLOX: NO!
[BEEP]
[FLATLINE TONE]
CAPTAIN: REPORT.
ANSWER ME!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
ARCHER: I IMAGINE THEY HAVE
THEIR HANDS FULL
RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
[DISTANT EXPLOSIONS]
ARCHER: I BELIEVE
THAT'S THE SH'RAAN.
SHE'S A VULCAN COMBAT CRUISER.
ONE OF THEIR MOST POWERFUL,
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN.
[BEEP]
HOSHI: SIR, THE CAPTAIN OF THE
SH'RAAN WANTS TO SPEAK TO YOU.
ARCHER: PUT IT UP.
CAPTAIN ARCHER,
ARE YOU IN ANY DANGER?
ARCHER: YOU COULD SAY THAT.
TELL THE MAZARITES TO TURN
THEIR WEAPONS OVER IMMEDIATELY
OR WE'LL DESTROY THEIR SHIPS.
WE'LL BE STANDING BY, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: THANK YOU.
CAPTAIN: WE DID
WHAT WE CAME TO DO.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
V'LAR: I AM SORRY
TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO ADDING THIS INCIDENT
TO MY TESTIMONY AT YOUR TRIAL.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
FEBRUARY 9, 2152.
THE VULCANS HAVE ALLOWED
THE MAZARITES TO LEAVE.
AMBASSADOR V'LAR SAYS THERE'S
A GOOD REASON FOR DOING SO,
THOUGH SHE'S CERTAINLY NOT
SHARING IT WITH ME.
[V'LAR SIGHS]
V'LAR: SOMEDAY I'D LIKE TO
WALK INTO A ROOM
WITHOUT IT SEEMING LIKE
A STATE VISIT.
ARCHER: OCCUPATIONAL HAZARD?
V'LAR: I'LL BE ALONG
IN A MOMENT.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I'M SORRY FOR THE TROUBLE I'VE
CAUSED YOU AND YOUR CREW.
ARCHER:
WE'RE GLAD WE COULD HELP.
V'LAR: I SENSE A GREAT
BOND BETWEEN YOU.
A BOND OF TRUST AND RESPECT.
BUT ALSO A BOND OF FRIENDSHIP.
I THINK IT BODES WELL
FOR THE FUTURE RELATIONS
OF OUR TWO PEOPLES.
GOOD-BYE, AMBASSADOR.
V'LAR: LIVE LONG AND PROSPER.