ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S PERSONAL LOG,
FEBRUARY 12, 2152.
AFTER A BRIEF DETOUR,
WE'RE BACK ON COURSE FOR RISA.
EVERYONE'S LOOKING FORWARD TO
SOME MUCH NEEDED SHORE LEAVE.
I'VE GOT MY EYE ON A PLACE
CALLED SURAYA BAY.
VILLAS BUILT
RIGHT INTO THE CLIFFS.
A PERFECT SPOT TO ENJOY
A FEW GOOD BOOKS.
MIGHT EVEN DO A LITTLE DIVING
WHEN I --
[ BEEPS ]
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
ARCHER.
We're picking up
a distress call, Captain.
It's coming from a vessel
approximately
two light-years to port.
ANY IDEA WHO IT IS?
No, sir.
Should we alter course?
GO AHEAD.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
LOOKS LIKE YOUR WALK
ON THE BEACH WILL HAVE TO WAIT.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
PLASMA RESIDUE?
YOUR WARP INJECTORS
WERE FULL OF IT.
OH, I MUST BE MORE DILIGENT
ABOUT ROUTINE MAINTENANCE.
UNLESS YOU ENJOY BEING ADRIFT
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
I'M SORRY TO INCONVENIENCE YOU
WITH SOMETHING THIS TRIVIAL.
BE SURE TO THANK MR. TUCKER
FOR HIS TIME.
HE WANTED ME TO THANK YOU.
IT ISN'T EVERY DAY HE GETS
TO TINKER WITH ALIEN ENGINES.
WE ALSO FOUND A MICROFRACTURE
ON YOUR STARBOARD HULL.
THEY'RE SEALING IT NOW.
-YOUR CREW IS VERY THOROUGH.
-WE WERE GLAD TO HELP.
DO YOU ANSWER EVERY
DISTRESS CALL YOU PICK UP?
IF WE CAN.
THE GALAXY COULD USE
MORE PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
TOMORROW --
YOU'LL JOIN ME IN MY HOME!
BRING COMMANDER TUCKER.
I'LL PREPARE A MEAL
IN YOUR HONOR.
IT'S THE LEAST I CAN DO
TO SHOW MY GRATITUDE.
THAT'S VERY GENEROUS,
BUT I PROMISED MY CREW
A TRIP TO RISA.
THAT CAN WAIT ONE MORE DAY,
CAN'T IT?
ARCHER: IF I PUT THEM OFF
MUCH LONGER, HEH,
I'M GOING TO HAVE
A MUTINY ON MY HANDS.
THERE'S GOING TO BE
A GESKANA MATCH.
I DOUBT YOU'VE EVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
GESKANA?
YES, YOU MIGHT WANT
TO PARTICIPATE,
ASSUMING YOU ENJOY COMPETITION.
I SHOULD WARN YOU, CAPTAIN,
I AM EASILY OFFENDED.
-SEND ME THE COORDINATES.
-[ CHUCKLES ]
-I'LL BREAK THE NEWS TO MY CREW.
-DRESS FOR WARM WEATHER.
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME
TO YOU, CAPTAIN,
I'LL SIT THIS ONE OUT.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU
TO PASS UP AN AWAY MISSION.
WELL, I'M UP TO MY EARS IN WORK.
THE IMPULSE MANIFOLDS
NEED TO BE PURGED,
THE GRAVITY PLATING ON "C" DECK
STILL ISN'T ALIGNED.
-TRIP.
-THE DESERT, SIR?
THE HEAT, THE DRY AIR.
YOU KNOW HOW
IT SUCKS THE LIFE OUT OF ME.
WHAT ABOUT THE TWO WEEKS
WE SPENT IN AUSTRALIA?
WE HAD A GREAT TIME.
TUCKER: SURVIVAL TRAINING
IN THE OUTBACK?
DRINKING RECYCLED SWEAT
AND EATING SNAKE MEAT?
THAT'S YOUR IDEA
OF A GREAT TIME?
IT'S NOT GONNA BE LIKE THAT.
I GET THE FEELING ZOBRAL'S A MAN
WHO LIKES TO INDULGE HIS GUESTS.
HE'S PROMISED TO ROLL OUT
THE RED CARPET FOR US.
IT'LL BE MORE FUN
THAN PURGING IMPULSE MANIFOLDS.
ARCHER: WELL, SUIT YOURSELF.
I'LL SEE
IF MALCOLM'S INTERESTED.
BUT I WAS HOPING YOU'D ENJOY
SPENDING SOME TIME
WITH YOUR CAPTAIN.
PROMISE WE WON'T HAVE
TO EAT ANY SNAKE MEAT?
IT'S HOTTER THAN HELL OUT THERE.
41 DEGREES.
IT'S A DRY HEAT.
ZOBRAL: HA HA! WELCOME!
ARCHER: GOOD TO BE HERE.
YOU REMEMBER COMMANDER TUCKER.
YES!
OF COURSE, OF COURSE.
THIS IS THE MAN
WHO REPAIRED MY SHIP.
A BRILLIANT ENGINEER.
TUCKER: AH, IT WAS JUST
A COUPLE OF CLOGGED INJECTORS.
OH, YOU ARE FAR TOO MODEST.
WELL, I HOPE YOU'RE HUNGRY.
I'VE PREPARED QUITE A FEAST.
ARE THERE MANY DESERTS
ON YOUR WORLD?
ARCHER: QUITE A FEW,
BUT NONE AS BIG AS THIS ONE.
TUCKER: FROM ORBIT,
YOU'D THINK
THE ENTIRE PLANET'S
NOTHING BUT SAND.
AH, WELL, WE HAVE A HANDFUL
OF LAKES AND SMALL SEAS.
WHAT ABOUT EARTH?
TWO-THIRDS WATER.
EXTRAORDINARY.
MORE WINE?
HMM. PLEASE.
WHAT'S THAT CALLED AGAIN?
YALASAT.
IT'S MADE FROM A CACTUS THAT
GROWS IN THE NORTHERN FOOTHILLS.
HOW IS YOUR ROAST TERACAQ?
ARCHER: IT'S VERY GOOD.
WHEN TRIP AND I DID
OUR SURVIVAL TRAINING --
[ CHUCKLES ] -- IN THE DESERT,
WE NEVER ATE THIS WELL.
WE MUST HAVE LOST
ABOUT THREE KILOS
DURING THAT LAST WEEK.
THE HEAT ALWAYS TAKES AWAY
MY APPETITE.
DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
BOTHERING YOU NOW.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I GUESS I'M GETTING ACCLIMATED.
AH. IT MUST BE DIFFICULT
ADJUSTING TO NEW CULTURES.
IT'S CHALLENGING
AT TIMES, BUT...
THAT'S WHY WE'RE OUT HERE.
DID YOU EVER THINK
OF TURNING BACK?
ONLY ONCE.
WE WERE ATTACKED
BY A HOSTILE SPECIES
WITH A LOT MORE FIREPOWER
THAN ENTERPRISE.
I SET A COURSE BACK TO EARTH
TO UPGRADE OUR WEAPONS.
BUT WE ENDED UP HAVING TO DO
THE REPAIRS OURSELVES.
TUCKER: THEY HAVEN'T
BOTHERED US SINCE.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE HAD
AN EVENTFUL JOURNEY.
ARCHER: IT'S HAD ITS SHARE
OF SURPRISES. HEH!
ZOBRAL: WELL, PERHAPS YOUR VISIT
HERE WILL BE ONE OF THEM.
OH! YOU'RE GOING TO ENJOY THIS!
ARCHER: OH. LOOKS DELICIOUS.
WHAT IS IT?
BLOOD SOUP.
I DON'T USUALLY EAT THIS WELL,
BUT I PROMISED YOUR CAPTAIN
AN EXCEPTIONAL MEAL.
WHAT ARE THESE, UH...
LITTLE CHUNKS?
UH, THE ESSENCE OF THE MALE,
CHOPPED AND SEASONED.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BEAUTIFUL TAPESTRIES.
ZOBRAL: THANK YOU.
WHICH ONE DO YOU PREFER?
UH...
-MMM.
-WELL...
THAT ONE'S INTERESTING.
[ GRUNTS ]
IT'S YOURS!
ARCHER: NO, NO, NO, NO.
I COULDN'T.
ZOBRAL: PLEASE,
CONSIDER IT A GIFT.
YOU'RE FAR TOO GENEROUS.
BESIDES, I WOULDN'T HAVE
ANY PLACE TO HANG IT.
SOMETHING...SMALLER, THEN.
AH.
I KNOW YOU WILL APPRECIATE THIS.
A SULIBAN MADE IT.
A SULIBAN I MET
SEVERAL YEARS AGO.
INTERESTING PEOPLE,
DON'T YOU AGREE?
THANK YOU.
[ DISTANT HORN BLOWS ]
AH, THE GESKANA MATCH
IS ABOUT TO BEGIN.
I'M HOPING YOU WILL
HONOR US BY PARTICIPATING.
TUCKER: NOW?
I JUST ATE A HALF A TERACAQ.
AH, YOU WILL BE GLAD YOU DID.
GESKANA REQUIRES
A GREAT DEAL OF STRENGTH.
AH!
[ GRUNTING ]
EH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
WOW.
THINK YOU'RE READY?
I'LL GIVE IT A SHOT, CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T PROMISE
WE'LL WIN ANY TROPHIES.
THIS IS AN IDEAL GAME
FOR MEN LIKE YOU.
THANKS.
[ BEEPS ]
-WE'RE BEING HAILED.
-THE CAPTAIN?
NO, IT'S COMING FROM A CITY
ON THE FAR SIDE OF THE DESERT.
PUT IT THROUGH.
THIS IS ENTERPRISE.
SEVERAL HOURS AGO,
YOU LAUNCHED A SMALL VESSEL
TO AN ENCAMPMENT
IN THE CYGNIAI EXPANSE.
WOULD YOU TELL ME WHY?
OUR CAPTAIN AND CHIEF ENGINEER
WERE INVITED.
-BY WHOM?
-A MAN NAMED ZOBRAL.
AND YOU ARE?
CHANCELLOR TRELIT.
WHY ARE YOU IN CONTACT
WITH THIS MAN?
HIS SHIP WAS DAMAGED,
AND WE ASSISTED HIM.
IN RETURN, HE OFFERED
HIS HOSPITALITY.
HOSPITALITY?
I HOPE YOU'RE AWARE
THAT MOST LIKELY,
YOU'LL NEVER SEE YOUR CAPTAIN
OR ENGINEER AGAIN.
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING,
GRUNTING ]
-YOU ALL RIGHT?
-NEVER BETTER.
MAN: HERE!
SECOND MAN: BLOCK OUT!
MAN: HERE! HERE!
GET IN FRONT OF IT!
CUT HIM OFF!
NOW!
OH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
-SO CLOSE!
-GOOD SHOT.
NEXT TIME.
TWO CENTIMETERS TO THE RIGHT,
AND YOU WOULD'VE HAD IT.
NEXT TIME, I'LL SET YOU UP
WITH A NO-LOOK PASS.
ALL RIGHT.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ZOBRAL: AH! HERE, HERE.
ARCHER.
I need to speak to you, Captain.
[ SCOFFS ]
CAN'T IT WAIT?
WE'RE A LITTLE BUSY
AT THE MOMENT.
It's urgent.
Are you alone?
HOLD ON A MINUTE.
IT'S MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
SHE SAYS IT'S IMPORTANT.
DO YOU MIND?
TAKE YOUR TIME. HEH!
HA HA! CATCH YOUR BREATH.
What's the problem?
I HAVE BEEN CONTACTED BY
A GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL IN A CITY
ABOUT 200 KILOMETERS
FROM WHERE YOU ARE NOW.
HE CLAIMS THAT YOU'RE IN DANGER.
WHAT KIND OF DANGER?
According to him,
ZOBRAL AND HIS MEN
ARE TERRORISTS.
They've been responsible
for numerous attacks
on civilian targets
within the city.
MAYBE I'M WRONG, BUT THEY DON'T
SEEM LIKE TERRORISTS TO ME.
PERHAPS NOT.
BUT UNTIL WE'RE CERTAIN
WHO THEY ARE,
I SUGGEST YOU RETURN
TO THE SHIP.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
I HOPE EVERYTHING IS ALL RIGHT.
ARCHER: THE PROBLEM WITH BEING
A STARSHIP CAPTAIN IS
YOU'RE NEVER REALLY OFF DUTY.
I'M AFRAID WE HAVE TO
CUT OUR VISIT SHORT.
OH, I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
PROBLEM WITH
THE STARBOARD ENGINE.
T'POL SAYS SHE NEEDS US
UP THERE RIGHT AWAY.
CAN'T WE AT LEAST
FINISH THIS QUARTER?
REMEMBER THOSE IMPULSE MANIFOLDS
YOU SAID NEEDED PURGING?
YOU WERE RIGHT.
WELL, THANKS
FOR ONE HELL OF A GAME.
YOU MUST HAVE OTHER PEOPLE
THAT CAN CORRECT THIS PROBLEM.
I WISH WE DID.
ZOBRAL: AS I SAID, CAPTAIN,
I AM EASILY OFFENDED.
WE'LL COME BACK IF THERE'S TIME.
I PROMISE.
ZOBRAL: YOU SHOULD NOT
BELIEVE THE TOROTHANS!
I HAVE JUST BEEN INFORMED
THAT WE PICKED UP
A LENGTHY TRANSMISSION
BETWEEN YOUR VESSEL
AND CHANCELLOR TRELIT.
WHATEVER HE TOLD YOUR
SCIENCE OFFICER, IT IS NOT TRUE!
I WANTED THIS TO WAIT
TILL LATER, BUT I BEG YOU,
LET ME EXPLAIN THE REAL REASON
WHY I ASKED YOU HERE.
YOU HAVE A REPUTATION
FOR BEING FAIR,
A MAN OF GREAT INTEGRITY.
WHEN YOU HEAR WHAT I
HAVE TO SAY,
I AM CERTAIN
YOU WILL WANT TO HELP US.
IT IS CALLED A YROTT.
THE WORD MEANS "TO STAND APART."
WHEN WE LIVED IN THE CITIES,
WE WERE FORCED TO WEAR THESE
WHENEVER WE WALKED IN PUBLIC.
ARCHER: I TAKE IT
THOSE DAYS ARE OVER.
WHEN THE CASTE SYSTEM
WAS FINALLY ABOLISHED,
WE WERE LED TO BELIEVE
THAT EVERYONE
WOULD BE TREATED EQUALLY.
I REMEMBER THE CELEBRATIONS --
YROTTS BEING BURNED
IN THE STREETS,
PEOPLE SAYING THAT WE HAD
FINALLY BEEN GRANTED OUR RIGHTS.
THE TOROTHAN CLAN
SIGNED THE ACCORD,
BUT THEY NEVER ABIDED BY IT.
ZOBRAL: THEY STILL CONTROL
THE GOVERNMENT, THE LANDS,
THE RESOURCES, EVERYTHING.
WE SPENT 10 YEARS
STAGING PROTESTS,
APPEALING TO THE COURTS,
UNTIL FINALLY WE REALIZED
THERE WAS ONLY ONE WAY
TO GET THEIR ATTENTION.
WE HAVE HUNDREDS OF CAMPS
JUST LIKE THIS ONE
ALL ACROSS THE DESERT,
AND WE ARE GOING TO KEEP
ATTACKING THE TOROTHANS
UNTIL OUR VOICES ARE HEARD.
THEY CALL US TERRORISTS,
BUT THE TRUTH IS THEY HAVE BEEN
TERRORIZING US FOR CENTURIES.
YOU SAID YOU BROUGHT ME
DOWN HERE FOR A REASON.
I HAVE A FEELING IT WASN'T
TO HEAR A HISTORY LESSON.
MMM.
THE TOROTHANS HAVE TEN TIMES
AS MANY SOLDIERS AS WE DO.
WE WON'T LAST MUCH LONGER
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
I REALLY DON'T SEE
WHAT I CAN DO FOR YOU.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THEY SAID YOU WOULD BE HUMBLE.
[ LAUGHS ]
I SCANNED YOUR VESSEL.
YOU HAVE AN ARSENAL
OF POWERFUL WEAPONS.
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
I-I NEED YOUR WISDOM.
OUR CURRENT STRATEGY
ISN'T WORKING.
BUT I-I AM CONFIDENT
THAT TOGETHER,
WE CAN FIND ONE THAT DOES.
I WOULD BE HONORED
TO FIGHT ALONGSIDE YOU,
AS WOULD ALL OF MY MEN.
[ DISTANT EXPLOSION ]
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
TOROTHAN CRUISERS.
USUALLY THEY BEGIN
THEIR BOMBARDMENT AFTER DARK.
THEY'RE GETTING STARTED
EARLY TODAY.
ARCHER: I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'VE HEARD ABOUT ME,
BUT I THINK YOU'VE BEEN MISLED.
-WHAT ABOUT THE SULIBAN?
-WHAT ABOUT THEM?
ZOBRAL: YOU LIBERATED
A DETENTION CAMP,
FREED THOUSANDS OF PRISONERS.
[ DISTANT EXPLOSION ]
WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
A SULIBAN TRANSPORT CAPTAIN.
HE TOLD ME OF AN EXPLORER
WHO WAS ALSO A GREAT WARRIOR,
A MAN WHO HELPED THEM
DEFEAT AN ENTIRE ARMY--
CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
MAN: TWO CRUISERS, SIR--
THEY'VE HIT
ONE OF OUR PULSE CANNONS.
AH, PREPARE MY SHIP.
THIS WON'T LAST
MORE THAN A FEW HOURS.
WE'LL CONTINUE
THIS DISCUSSION LATER.
YOU'LL BE SAFE HERE.
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME TO YOU,
WE'D RATHER GET BACK
TO ENTERPRISE.
ZOBRAL: WELL,
YOUR SHUTTLE'S THRUSTERS
WOULD DRAW THEIR ATTENTION.
YOU'D BECOME AN EASY TARGET.
ZOBRAL: PLEASE.
I WOULDN'T BE A VERY GOOD HOST
IF I ALLOWED YOU TO GET KILLED.
[ DISTANT EXPLOSION ]
THERE'S A NUMBER OF SHIPS
STRAFING THE ENCAMPMENT.
HAIL THE CAPTAIN.
[ BEEPING ]
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
T'POL: CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
We've taken shelter...
should be --
THAT'S THE BEST I CAN GIVE YOU.
THE ENTIRE REGION IS FLOODED
WITH JAMMING SIGNALS.
WELL, WE CAN'T JUST
LEAVE THEM DOWN THERE.
WHAT ABOUT THE TRANSPORTER?
REED: I CAN'T LOCALIZE
THEIR BIO-SIGNS.
I'LL TAKE A SHUTTLEPOD
AND FIND THEM MYSELF.
IN THE MIDDLE OF AN ASSAULT?
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND
CHANCELLOR TRELIT.
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
THANKS.
ENTERPRISE.
RESPOND.
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
-OH, MAN.
-OH!
-ROUGH GAME.
-[ GROANS ]
THAT DAMN MIDFIELDER
KNOCKED ME DOWN THREE TIMES
DURING THE LAST QUARTER.
OH, I MUST'VE BRUISED
HALF A DOZEN RIBS.
BETTER HAVE DR. PHLOX TAKE
A LOOK AT IT WHEN WE GET BACK.
[ DISTANT EXPLOSION ]
SO DOES THE...GREAT WARRIOR
HAVE ANY IDEAS ABOUT HOW WE'RE
GETTING OUT OF HERE?
[ SIGHS ]
YOU'RE NOT THINKING
ABOUT HELPING THESE PEOPLE?
ARCHER: I WAS THINKING
ABOUT THOSE SULIBAN PRISONERS.
[ GRUNTS ]
IF WE HADN'T HELPED THEM ESCAPE,
WE WOULDN'T BE IN
THIS SITUATION.
AH. T'POL'S EARS
MUST BE BURNING.
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ GROANS ]
WANT YOUR
CHIEF ENGINEER'S ADVICE?
WHAT IS IT?
[ SIGHS ]
WALK AWAY.
THEY LURED US DOWN HERE
UNDER FALSE PRETENSES,
AND NOW THEY'RE ASKING US
TO HELP THEM FIGHT A WAR?
THAT'S A LOT DIFFERENT
THAN BREAKING
A FEW INNOCENT PEOPLE
OUT OF PRISON.
ARCHER: THERE'S JUST
ONE PROBLEM -- ZOBRAL.
I GET THE FEELING HE'S NOT
GONNA TAKE NO FOR AN ANSWER.
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ SPITS, COUGHING ]
COME ON.
[ COUGHING ]
[ EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE ]
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I'D RATHER TAKE MY CHANCES
OUT IN THAT DESERT.
THOUGHT YOU HATED THE DESERT.
NOT TONIGHT.
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ GRUNTS ]
YOU NEGLECTED TO MENTION
THAT YOU'D BE ATTACKING
THE ENCAMPMENT.
AND YOU ASSURED ME YOUR PEOPLE
WOULD BE LEAVING THE SURFACE.
WHY DIDN'T THEY?
CAPTAIN ARCHER WANTED
TO SPEAK WITH ZOBRAL.
INTERESTING.
WHERE ARE THEY NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
IF YOU'D BE WILLING
TO END YOUR ASSAULT,
WE COULD LAUNCH A SEARCH PARTY.
YOU EXPECT US TO STAND BY
WHILE YOU SEND MORE PEOPLE
TO JOIN ZOBRAL?
IF YOU BELIEVE WE'RE ASSISTING
THE TERRORISTS, YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
OF COURSE.
I FORGOT.
THEY JUST WENT DOWN
FOR THE HOSPITALITY.
LET US FIND THEM,
AND WE'LL LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU PROMISED BEFORE.
WE'LL LOCATE
YOUR MEN OURSELVES
AND DEAL WITH THEM
ACCORDINGLY.
THAT'S ASSUMING THEY HAVEN'T
ALREADY BEEN KILLED.
-CHANCELLOR --
-IF YOU ATTEMPT
TO LAUNCH ANOTHER SHUTTLECRAFT,
WE'LL HAVE NO CHOICE
BUT TO CONSIDER IT
AS AN ENEMY VESSEL.
I'VE LOST SENSOR CONTACT
WITH THE SURFACE.
SOME KIND OF ORBITAL
DISPERSION FIELD.
I CAN'T GET ANY READINGS BELOW
A HUNDRED KILOMETERS.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
TUCKER: TWO MEN
OUT IN THE OPEN.
YOU'D THINK THEY WOULD HAVE
SPOTTED US BY NOW.
WE'RE DOWN HERE!
ARCHER: YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
YELL A LITTLE LOUDER THAN THAT.
TUCKER: HUH!
[ GRUNTING ]
YOU SURE WE'RE GOING
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION?
ARCHER: IT WAS EAST OF THE CAMP.
WE'RE HEADING EAST.
HOW FAR?
ABOUT 30 KILOMETERS.
30?
WHAT IF WE FIND MORE
OF ZOBRAL'S MEN INSIDE?
ARCHER: IT LOOKED ABANDONED.
[ PANTING ]
TUCKER: ALL I SAW WAS SAND.
I DON'T REMEMBER ANY BUILDINGS.
ARCHER: THAT'S BECAUSE YOU
FORGOT YOUR SURVIVAL TRAINING.
TAKE A GOOD LOOK ON YOUR WAY IN
AT YOUR SURROUNDINGS.
TUCKER: DIDN'T THEY
ALSO SAY SOMETHING
ABOUT ONLY WALKING AT NIGHT?
OHH.
CAN'T WE WAIT
UNTIL IT COOLS DOWN A LITTLE?
THAT COULD BE FOR ANOTHER...
[ SIGHS ]
EIGHT OR NINE HOURS.
WE NEED TO FIND SHELTER.
20 MINUTES, CAPTAIN.
TRIP.
OH.
10?
[ GROANS ]
TO CHERRY-FLAVORED SNOW CONES.
WHAT I WOULDN'T GIVE FOR ONE
RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
OH.
[ DISTANT RUMBLING ]
YOU HEAR THAT?
WHAT?
SOUNDS LIKE A SHIP.
THINK THE HEAT'S
GETTING TO YOU.
NO.
LISTEN.
[ WHIRRING IN DISTANCE ]
OVER THERE.
A SHUTTLEPOD?
NO.
SOMETHING A LOT BIGGER.
[ COUGHS ]
-YOU ALL RIGHT?
-YEAH.
REED: A DISPERSION FIELD
COVERS HALF THE CONTINENT.
BUT IF I DISABLE
THESE THREE SATELLITES,
I THINK I CAN GET A CLEAR
READING OF THE EASTERN DESERT.
THAT MIGHT PROVOKE
THE TOROTHANS.
I SUGGEST YOU TRY TO FIND
A LESS INTRUSIVE WAY
TO PENETRATE THEIR DEFENSES.
WHY MONTANA?
OF ALL THE PLACES THE VULCANS
COULD HAVE LANDED,
THEY CHOSE BOZEMAN, MONTANA.
HUMANITY'S FIRST WARP DRIVE
WAS DEVELOPED THERE.
IT SEEMED A LOGICAL PLACE
TO BEGIN.
WELL, HOW DID THEY KNOW IT
WOULDN'T ALARM OTHER NATIONS?
AN ALIEN SPECIES MAKES CONTACT
WITH THE UNITED STATES.
COULD HAVE MADE A LOT
OF OTHER COUNTRIES NERVOUS.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
IT SEEMS TO ME THAT WE'RE GONNA
RUN INTO SIMILAR PROBLEMS.
WE GET INVITED TO DINNER,
AND BEFORE YOU KNOW IT,
WE'RE ACCUSED
OF TAKING SIDES IN A WAR.
CONTACTING NEW WORLDS ALWAYS
INVOLVES UNEXPECTED RISKS.
THE HIGH COMMAND HAS
VERY SPECIFIC PROTOCOLS
REGARDING PLANETARY CONFLICTS.
EVENTUALLY, CAPTAIN ARCHER
WILL HAVE TO
CREATE SOME DIRECTIVES
OF HIS OWN.
COME ON. COME ON.
WE GOT TO KEEP MOVING.
COME ON.
MY SHIFT DOESN'T BEGIN
FOR ANOTHER SIX HOURS.
HEY...
WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
WHERE?
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
NICE LITTLE PLACE I KNOW.
PLENTY OF SHADE.
ARE THERE BLANKETS DOWN THERE?
-HUH?
-I'M FREEZING.
HEAT EXHAUSTION.
-[ GRUNTS ]
-COME HERE.
HERE.
THERE YOU GO.
EASY, EASY.
TAKE MINE. GO AHEAD.
NO, SIR. I WON'T TAKE
ANOTHER MAN'S WATER.
YOU DRINK IT.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ GROANS ]
GOT TO KEEP MOVING.
TAKE THE WATER
OR I'LL KNOCK YOU
ON YOUR ASS AND POUR IT
DOWN YOUR THROAT.
EASY.
THANKS.
OH!
[ GRUNTS ]
THERE'S A VESSEL APPROACHING
FROM THE SURFACE.
IT'S ZOBRAL.
-[ BEEPS ]
-HE'S HAILING US.
Open your launch doors.
Quickly!
IS THE CAPTAIN WITH YOU?
COMMANDER TUCKER?
No, no,
I'll explain once I'm aboard.
WHERE ARE THEY?
If I'm not in your docking bay
in the next 30 seconds,
I'll be detected.
They'll destroy my ship.
BRING HIM IN.
-HOW MANY?
-THERE WERE 89.
THERE WERE ONLY 89 SULIBAN,
NOT THOUSANDS.
ZOBRAL: MMM.
AND THE ARMY YOU DEFEATED?
REED: I WOULD HARDLY
CALL IT AN ARMY.
IT WAS MORE LIKE
A FEW DOZEN PRISON GUARDS.
AND TO BE HONEST, THEY DIDN'T
PUT UP MUCH OF A FIGHT.
T'POL: JONATHAN ARCHER IS
AN EXCELLENT STARSHIP CAPTAIN,
BUT HE'S HARDLY THE INVINCIBLE
WARRIOR DESCRIBED TO YOU.
HMM. WHAT ABOUT HIS
LEGENDARY DESERT TACTICS?
ACTUALLY, I'M THE TACTICAL
OFFICER ON THIS SHIP,
AND I DON'T HAVE ANY EXPERIENCE
AT WAGING DESERT WARFARE.
I'M AFRAID YOU'VE COME
TO THE WRONG PEOPLE FOR HELP.
MMM, ALL THIS FOR NOTHING.
WHAT ABOUT OUR PEOPLE?
WELL, YOU HAVE FAR BETTER
SENSORS THAN WE DO.
I'M SURE YOU'LL FIND THEM.
T'POL: OUR SENSORS ARE
BEING DISRUPTED,
AND THE TOROTHANS HAVE
THREATENED TO FIRE ON US
IF WE LAUNCH A SHUTTLEPOD.
HOW DID YOU GET HERE
WITHOUT THEM SEEING YOU?
THERE IS A NARROW GAP
IN THEIR ORBITAL DETECTION GRID.
IT OCCURS ONCE EVERY 46 MINUTES,
BUT IT IS ONLY OPEN
FOR LESS THAN ONE MINUTE.
I'LL NEED ALL
THE PERTINENT DATA.
ZOBRAL: HA!
YOU'LL NEED MORE THAN THAT!
THE MANEUVERS
ARE EXTREMELY DIFFICULT.
IT TOOK US YEARS TO LEARN THEM.
I'M A QUICK STUDY.
YOU WILL BE SHOT DOWN
BEFORE YOU REACH THE ATMOSPHERE.
WITH YOU AT THE HELM,
OUR CHANCES WOULD IMPROVE.
ZOBRAL: I DON'T HAVE TIME!
MY MEN ARE WAITING FOR ME!
REED: THEN THEY'LL HAVE
TO WAIT A LITTLE LONGER.
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT GOT
OUR PEOPLE STRANDED DOWN THERE.
THEY ARE NOT MY RESPONSIBILITY!
T'POL: YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
THE TOROTHANS BELIEVE
WE'VE JOINED YOUR CAUSE.
IF CAPTAIN ARCHER
AND COMMANDER TUCKER
ARE APPREHENDED,
THEY'LL UNDOUBTEDLY
BE TREATED AS MEMBERS
OF YOUR CLAN.
THEY'LL BECOME VICTIMS
OF THE SAME OPPRESSION
YOU'VE BEEN FIGHTING
ALL THESE YEARS.
YOU SHOULD FEEL AS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THOSE TWO MEN
AS YOU DO FOR YOUR OWN.
[ PANTING ]
OH.
[ GRUNTING ]
EASY.
HOME SWEET HOME.
AH! HA!
I HOPE YOU'RE NOT PLANNING
TO HOG THAT ALL FOR YOURSELF.
HA!
[ SNIFFS ]
WATER'S OFF THE MENU.
OH...OH.
NOW, THIS...
IS MY IDEA OF A GREAT TIME.
WHAT'D YOU DO...
RUB...TWO STICKS TOGETHER?
ARCHER: I FOUND A NEW USE
FOR THE STUN SETTING.
IT MAY NOT TASTE
TOO GOOD, BUT...
I THINK I BOILED AWAY ANYTHING
THAT CAN HURT US.
NO, THANKS.
I'M NOT THIRSTY.
LET'S NOT GET INTO
THAT ARGUMENT AGAIN.
WORSE THAN BLOOD SOUP.
-YOU NEED WATER.
-[ SIGHS ]
WHAT I NEED...
IS SLEEP.
YOU GOT A FEVER, TRIP.
YOUR HEART'S RACING.
YOU GOT ALL
THE SYMPTOMS OF HEATSTROKE.
IF YOU FALL ASLEEP,
YOU COULD LAPSE INTO A COMA.
A COMA?
THAT SOUNDS NICE.
WHEN WE GET BACK TO ENTERPRISE,
YOU CAN SLEEP ALL YOU WANT,
BUT RIGHT NOW,
YOU GOT TO STAY WITH ME
AND DRINK THIS WATER.
IF I HAD A NEEDLE, I'D GIVE IT
TO YOU INTRAVENOUSLY,
BUT I DON'T.
COME ON. SIT UP.
THERE YOU GO.
GOOD.
[ COUGHING ]
YEAH.
COMMANDER.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
THE WARP REACTOR...
BREAK IT DOWN FOR ME.
WHAT?
WHAT ARE THE EIGHT
MAJOR COMPONENTS?
YOU GOT TO BE KIDDING ME.
NAME THEM.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
WELL...
THERE'S THE DRUMSTICKS...
THIGHS...
WINGS.
YOU GOT ANYTHING TO EAT
AROUND HERE?
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
BUT WHEN WE GET BACK
TO ENTERPRISE,
I'LL HAVE CHEF MAKE YOU A DINNER
YOU'LL NEVER FORGET.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
ANYTHING.
NOT SNAKE MEAT.
NO, CHEF DOESN'T DO SNAKE
VERY WELL.
TELL ME WHAT YOU WANT.
PRIME RIB.
OKAY. WHAT ELSE?
MASHED POTATOES
WITH M-MUSHROOM GRAVY.
THE -- THE KIND HE MAKES
ON WEDNESDAY NIGHTS.
NO PROBLEM.
WHAT KIND OF VEGETABLES?
HEY. VEGETABLES?
-BROCCOLI.
-AH.
DESSERT?
-PECAN PIE.
-AH.
TAKE ANOTHER PASS OVER
THE EASTERN BASIN.
OUR SENSORS
WOULD HAVE DETECTED THEM.
NO, THERE'S MAGNETIC DEPOSITS
BELOW THAT BASIN.
THEY COULD BE MASKING
THEIR BIO-SIGNS.
IF WE INCREASED OUR ALTITUDE,
THIS WOULD GO A LOT FASTER.
WE WOULD ALSO RISK
BEING DETECTED.
GEOGRAPHY.
DO YOU KNOW HOW TO PLAY?
GEOGRAPHY?
YOU KNOW,
YOU SAY "AMAZON RIVER,"
WHICH ENDS IN AN "R,"
AND THEN I SAY "RHODE ISLAND."
W-WE'RE GOING TO RHODE ISLAND?
NO.
NO, I-IT'S A GAME.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO TELL ME SOME PLACE
THAT STARTS WITH A "D."
[ SIGHS ]
OH.
"D."
UH...
DRAYLAX.
"X"?
"X..."
THERE'S ALWAYS --
NO, NO.
NO, DON'T TELL ME.
I KNOW AN "X."
[ SCOFFS ]
XANADU.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THAT'S NOT A REAL PLACE.
-IT DOESN'T MATTER.
-AH, OF COURSE IT MATTERS.
ARCHER: YOU JUST USED
AN ALIEN PLANET -- DRAYLAX.
[ COUGHING ]
EASY. EASY.
HERE.
EASY, EASY.
[ DISTANT EXPLOSION ]
[ EXPLOSION ]
ALL RIGHT.
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
XANADU'S FINE.
GET YOUR HEAD DOWN!
-WHAT?
-GET DOWN!
[ COUGHING ]
WE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE!
COME ON.
[ GROANS ]
I'M PICKING UP WEAPONS FIRE
ON THE SURFACE.
19 KILOMETERS DUE SOUTH.
A TOROTHAN MORTAR.
WOULD THEY BE TARGETING
ONE OF YOUR SETTLEMENTS?
ZOBRAL: WE DON'T HAVE
ANY NEAR THERE.
SET A COURSE
AND PREPARE TO FIRE.
I BELIEVE THEY'VE LOCATED THE
CAPTAIN AND COMMANDER TUCKER.
COME ON.
-COME ON.
-[ GROANS ]
[ BEEPING ]
I'VE GOT A LOCK.
FIRE.
I SEE THEM.
TWO HUMANS.
BEARING 115, MARK 3.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
TUCKER: I'M JUST
SLOWING YOU DOWN. GO!
ARCHER: I DON'T REMEMBER
TAKING ORDERS FROM YOU.
[ GRUNTING ]
MY LAUNCH WINDOW OPENS
IN NINE MINUTES.
I SHOULD BE GOING.
I HOPE COMMANDER TUCKER
IS GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I DOUBT I'LL EVER CONVINCE HIM
TO SET FOOT ON ANOTHER DESERT,
BUT...HE'LL BE FINE.
ZOBRAL, EVEN IF I WERE
THE WARRIOR YOU THOUGHT I WAS...
THAT'S NOT WHY
WE'RE OUT HERE.
CAPTAIN.
ZOBRAL: SUBCOMMANDER.
WHAT YOU TOLD HIM WAS CORRECT.
DECISIONS TO GET INVOLVED
IN THE CONFLICTS OF OTHER WORLDS
SHOULD BE LEFT TO GOVERNMENTS,
NOT STARSHIP CAPTAINS.
I KNOW.
THE IRONY IS I HAVE THE FEELING
HIS CAUSE IS WORTH FIGHTING FOR.