ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S PERSONAL LOG,
FEBRUARY 18, 2152.
IT TOOK A WHILE, BUT WE'VE
FINALLY MADE IT TO RISA.
WITH ANY LUCK,
THIS'LL BE MY LAST LOG ENTRY
FOR THE NEXT TWO DAYS.
[PORTHOS BARKS]
ARCHER: IF ANYTHING HAPPENS,
YOU KNOW WHERE TO REACH ME.
T'POL: I DON'T ANTICIPATE
ANY PROBLEMS.
ARCHER: WELL, IT'S THE PROBLEMS
YOU DON'T ANTICIPATE.
T'POL: THE CREW IS TRAINED
TO HANDLE EMERGENCIES.
BUT I'LL ALERT YOU IMMEDIATELY
IF THERE ARE ANY PROBLEMS.
ARCHER: THIS DOESN'T FEEL RIGHT.
I SHOULDN'T BE GOING DOWN
TO SOME PLEASURE PLANET
WHILE HALF THE CREW
HAS TO STAY ON BOARD.
T'POL: EVERYONE DREW LOTS.
YOU HAD THE SAME CHANCE
AS THE OTHERS.
ARCHER: ALL THE SAME,
THE CREW SHOULD COME FIRST.
T'POL: CAPTAIN,
YOU NEED A VACATION.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
I'M GLAD YOU DECIDED
TO TAKE SOME TIME OFF, SIR.
ARCHER: WOULDN'T MISS IT.
MAN: DO YOU WANT TO TAKE
THE HELM, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: I'M ON VACATION.
THANKS.
ENJOY YOURSELVES.
TUCKER: I'LL BRING YOU
A SOUVENIR.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: EVERYONE HAVE
BIG PLANS? TRAVIS?
TRAVIS: ROCK-CLIMBING, SIR.
THERE'S A PLACE CALLED GALARTHA.
THE CLIFF FACE CHANGES PITCH
WHILE YOU CLIMB IT.
HOSHI: THAT SOUNDS
KIND OF DANGEROUS.
TRAVIS: WELL, IF IT'S EASY,
WHAT'S THE POINT?
ARCHER: JUST WATCH YOURSELF.
MALCOLM.
REED: WELL, SUPPOSEDLY
RISA'S VERY COSMOPOLITAN.
THERE ARE SPECIES
VISITING FROM ALL OVER.
MALCOLM AND I PLAN TO, UH...
BROADEN OUR CULTURAL HORIZONS.
HOSHI: IS THAT ALL
YOU TWO THINK ABOUT?
WELL, HOW WE CHOOSE TO RELAX
IS OUR OWN BUSINESS.
[REED LAUGHS]
ARCHER: YOU WATCH
YOURSELVES, TOO.
HOSHI: I PLAN ON DOING SOMETHING
CONSTRUCTIVE WITH MY TIME.
I HAVE BEEN RELYING
ON THE UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR
FAR TOO MUCH.
BEFORE I LEFT EARTH,
I LEARNED 38 LANGUAGES,
AND NOW ALL I DO
IS PUSH A BUTTON
AND THE COMPUTER
DOES ALL THE WORK.
MAN: ISN'T THAT WHAT IT'S FOR?
HOSHI: NOT THIS TIME.
I LEFT MY TRANSLATOR
ON "ENTERPRISE."
TUCKER: YOU ONLY HAVE
TWO DAYS, HOSHI.
IF YOU WANT TO WASTE YOUR TIME
TALKING TO PEOPLE...
[REED CHUCKLES]
WHAT ABOUT YOU, CAPTAIN?
I'VE NEVER BEEN MUCH
FOR VACATIONS,
BUT I'VE GOT A LITTLE VILLA
OVERLOOKING THE OCEAN,
AND, UH, PORTHOS AND I
ARE GOING TO RELAX.
T'POL: HOW LONG WILL THIS LAST?
PHLOX: I USUALLY REQUIRE
6 DAYS PER YEAR,
BUT TWO SHOULD LEAVE ME
SUFFICIENTLY REFRESHED.
I'VE ADJUSTED THE DOSAGE TO
WAKE YOU UP IN EXACTLY 48 HOURS.
T'POL: AND IF SOMEONE SHOULD
REQUIRE MEDICAL ATTENTION
DURING YOUR HIBERNATION?
PHLOX: CREWMAN CUTLER
IS A CAPABLE MEDIC.
CUTLER: I KNOW WHERE
THE BANDAGES ARE.
PHLOX: YOU CAN ALWAYS WAKE ME
IF YOU NEED TO,
BUT, PLEASE, ONLY
IF IT'S AN EMERGENCY, HMM?
CUTLER: OH.
PHLOX: WELL...TO BED.
T'POL: PLEASANT DREAMS, DOCTOR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, PORTHOS?
NOT BAD.
[DOG BARKING]
COME HERE. LET'S GO.
WHAT ARE YOU BARKING AT?
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
TUCKER: WHAT ABOUT THAT ONE?
REED: HA HA! NOW I KNOW
YOU'VE BEEN COOPED UP
ON A STARSHIP FOR TOO LONG.
TUCKER: NO, WHAT'S
WRONG WITH HER?
REED: WELL, NOTHING, I SUPPOSE.
I JUST WOULDN'T KNOW
WHICH EYES TO LOOK INTO.
[BOTH LAUGH]
REED: HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
NOW, SHE'S INTERESTING.
TUCKER: I DON'T THINK
"SHE" IS THE RIGHT PRONOUN, HMM?
BUT IF YOU THINK
IT'S WORTH THE RISK...
REED: I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE I SHOULD HAVE BROUGHT
MY SCANNER WITH ME.
[TUCKER LAUGHS]
REED: OH. THANK YOU.
TUCKER: THAT'S A SHE.
REED: UH-HUH.
NOW, WHAT SHALL WE DRINK TO?
TUCKER: TO US AND...
TO A WELL-EARNED
TWO DAYS AND TWO NIGHTS.
[DOG BARKS]
[DOGS BARKING]
HOW'D YOU GET UP HERE?
[GROWLING]
STOP IT, YOU TWO.
PORTHOS.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN!
WOMAN: I'M SORRY TO BOTHER YOU,
BUT I THINK MY DOG
IS ON YOUR DECK.
ARCHER: PLEASE.
THERE YOU ARE.
I HOPE SHE DIDN'T HURT...
ARCHER: PORTHOS.
WOMAN: HELLO, PORTHOS.
SHE'S BEEN COOPED UP FOR WEEKS.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN SHE'D RUN
OFF THE FIRST CHANCE SHE GOT.
ARCHER: OH, NO HARM DONE.
SHE PROBABLY JUST CAME OVER
TO MAKE A FRIEND.
I'M JONATHAN.
WOMAN: KEYLA.
ARCHER: SO IS THIS
YOUR FIRST TIME TO RISA?
KEYLA: YES. YOU?
ARCHER: FIRST TIME.
MY SCIENCE OFFICER
FELT I NEEDED TO RELAX,
SO I DECIDED TO DO SOME READING,
LET PORTHOS RUN ON THE BEACH.
YOU SHOULD ALWAYS LISTEN
TO YOUR SCIENCE OFFICER.
SHE'D BE THE FIRST
TO AGREE WITH YOU.
I WAS ABOUT TO GO OUT
FOR DINNER.
CAN YOU RECOMMEND A RESTAURANT?
KEYLA: THERE'S THIS LITTLE BOAT
THAT SAILS INTO THE BAY
EVERY EVENING JUST AFTER SUNSET.
YOU WADE OUT, AND THEY SERVE
SEAFOOD RIGHT OFF THE DECK.
SOUNDS GREAT.
WELL, I'M SORRY TO DISTURB YOU.
THANKS AGAIN.
ARCHER: IF YOU DON'T
HAVE OTHER PLANS,
MAYBE WE COULD WADE OUT
TO THAT LITTLE BOAT TOGETHER.
KEYLA: YOU'RE NOT HERE
WITH YOUR SCIENCE OFFICER?
ARCHER: NO.
IN THAT CASE...
OH. NO, I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T TONIGHT.
ARCHER: JUST A THOUGHT.
KEYLA: TOMORROW?
ARCHER: I LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
KEYLA: SO DO I.
GOOD-BYE, PORTHOS.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
SLOWLY, PLEASE.
OH.
RAVIS.
MM-HMM.
[SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
HMM.
REED: THAT PLACE UP THE STREET
LOOKED PRETTY LIVELY.
TUCKER:
WELL, THE VULCAN DATABASE SAID
NO ONE LEAVES THIS CLUB UNHAPPY.
REED: HOW WOULD
THE VULCANS KNOW?
THEY ONLY MATE
ONCE EVERY 7 YEARS.
TUCKER: THAT'S WHAT THEY SAY.
REED: DO YOU KNOW
SOMETHING I DON'T?
TUCKER: COME ON. 7 YEARS?
I DOUBT EVEN T'POL
COULD HOLD OUT THAT LONG.
REED: OH, SHE'S
VERY DISCIPLINED.
TUCKER: MALCOLM, BEARING 180.
REED: WHAT?
TUCKER: BEHIND YOU.
ANYTHING IN THAT DATABASE
THAT COULD HELP US
GET A CONVERSATION GOING?
IF YOU WANTED TO HAVE
A CULTURAL DIALOGUE,
YOU SHOULD HAVE GONE WITH HOSHI.
WOMAN: HELLO.
TUCKER: HELLO.
WOMAN: I'M DEE'AHN,
AND THIS IS LATIA.
TUCKER: I'M TRIP.
REED: I'M MALCOLM.
WOULD YOU JOIN US FOR A DRINK?
DEE'AHN: WE'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU TO ASK.
REED: WELL, UH,
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
LATIA: THESE LOOK GOOD.
TUCKER: UH, ANOTHER
ROUND, PLEASE.
WOMAN: ALL RIGHT.
DEE'AHN: SO WHERE
ARE YOU TWO FROM?
REED: OUR PLANET'S CALLED EARTH.
LATIA: EARTH?
NEVER HEARD OF IT.
WE'RE SORT OF NEW
TO THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
DEE'AHN: WELL, THEN WE'LL
HAVE TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOUR FIRST VISIT TO RISA
IS MEMORABLE.
KEYLA: JONATHAN?
YOU'RE UP LATE.
ARCHER:
JUST LOOKING AT THE STARS.
DON'T YOU GET ENOUGH OF THAT
ON YOUR SHIP?
NEVER.
WILL YOU SHOW ME
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING AT?
COME ON UP.
I WANTED TO THANK YOU FOR THE
LITTLE BOAT WITH THE SEAFOOD.
BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
KEYLA: I'M SORRY YOU
HAD TO EAT ALONE.
ARCHER: OH, NO PROBLEM.
I HAD A NICE CHAT WITH A COUPLE
FROM VEGA RETICULI.
IT TURNS OUT IT'S THEIR
300th WEDDING ANNIVERSARY.
KEYLA: WELL, THEY MUST HAVE
A LOT OF STORIES.
ARCHER: YOU CAN'T IMAGINE.
THERE IT IS.
KEYLA: WHAT AM I LOOKING FOR?
SEE THE BRIGHT BLUE STAR
AT THE TOP?
IS THAT YOUR SUN?
ARCHER: NO, LOOK JUST BELOW.
THE YELLOW ONE.
DO YOU SEE IT?
IT'S SO FAINT.
AH, IT'S ABOUT 90 LIGHT-YEARS
FROM HERE.
YOU'RE A LONG WAY FROM HOME.
ACTUALLY, THIS IS THE FARTHEST
ANY OF MY PEOPLE HAVE EVER GONE.
YOU'RE AN EXPLORER.
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED IF
THEY'RE NAMING SCHOOLS AFTER YOU
BACK ON YOUR WORLD.
ARCHER: HEH! ARCHER ELEMENTARY.
IT HAS A NICE RING TO IT.
CAN YOU SHOW ME
WHERE YOU'RE FROM?
KEYLA: OH, I REALLY DON'T HAVE
A VERY GOOD SENSE OF DIRECTION.
ARCHER: OH, I'M SURE
IT'S NOT THAT BAD.
KEYLA: I GOT LOST COMING BACK
FROM THE LOBBY TODAY.
ARCHER: WELL...
I CAN SEE HOW THAT COULD HAPPEN.
I MEAN, IT'S AT LEAST
A HUNDRED METERS FROM HERE.
KEYLA: AND ALL THE VILLAS
LOOK THE SAME.
ARCHER: YOU'VE JUST GOT TO
NOTICE THE SUBTLE DIFFERENCES.
LIKE THE NUMBERS ON THE DOORS.
NOW YOU'RE CATCHING ON.
GIVE ME A COUPLE HOURS, I COULD
HAVE YOU NAVIGATING A STARSHIP.
WHY DON'T YOU START
BY TELLING ME
ABOUT SOME OF THE PLACES
YOU'VE BEEN?
WE'LL GET TO THE STARSHIP
NAVIGATION LATER.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
TUCKER: WE ONLY HAD A FEW HOURS
OF AIR LEFT,
SO I JETTISONED OUR ENGINE
AND BLEW IT UP.
TURNED IT INTO A RESCUE FLARE.
REED: IT WAS MY IDEA.
TUCKER: DOESN'T MATTER
WHOSE IDEA IT WAS.
IT WORKED.
REED: WHY DON'T YOU TELL THEM
ABOUT THE TIME
YOU SAVED "ENTERPRISE"
IN YOUR UNDERWEAR.
ARCHER: YEAH, I SAVED
THE CAPTAIN'S LIFE.
LATIA: I THOUGHT YOU
WERE THE CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: WE ROTATE.
HE'S CAPTAIN NEXT WEEK.
DEE'AHN: SO, CAPTAINS...
HAVE YOU SEEN
THE SUBTERRANEAN GARDENS?
REED: SUBTERRANEAN?
LATIA: ALL THE PLANTS
THAT GROW THERE ARE LUMINESCENT.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
REED: MMM.
TUCKER: MAYBE YOU COULD SHOW US.
LATIA: THROUGH HERE.
THIS IS A STRANGE WAY
TO GET TO THE GARDEN.
DEE'AHN: THEY'RE VERY SECLUDED.
SO HOW MUCH DO STARSHIP
CAPTAINS GET PAID ON YOUR WORLD?
REED: EXCUSE ME?
LATIA: WHAT KIND OF VALUABLES
DO YOU HAVE?
TUCKER: I THINK THERE'S BEEN
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
OH!
THERE'S DEFINITELY
BEEN A MISUNDERSTANDING.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
ALIEN: SEE WHAT THEY HAVE.
[TUCKER GROANING]
I HOPE THIS
ISN'T THEIR MATING RITUAL.
ALIEN: BE QUIET!
ALIEN: NOTHING!
ALIEN 2: MAYBE THEY HAVE
SOMETHING BACK IN THEIR ROOMS.
ALIEN: IT'S TOO RISKY.
WE COULD SELL THEIR CLOTHES.
TUCKER: LISTEN, I BET WE
COULD MAKE SOME KIND OF A DEAL.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
"ENTERPRISE."
TRAVIS: IT'S TRAVIS,
SUBCOMMANDER.
COULD YOU SEND
A SHUTTLEPOD DOWN?
T'POL: WHAT'S
THE PROBLEM, ENSIGN?
TRAVIS: I HAD A LITTLE
ROCK-CLIMBING ACCIDENT.
WHERE ARE YOU?
TRAVIS: IN THE CENTRAL HOSPITAL,
BUT I REALLY WANT
TO GET BACK TO "ENTERPRISE."
TRAVIS: THE FUN PART IS THE WAY
THE ROCK FACE CHANGES.
THE PROBLEM IS
THE HANDHOLDS CHANGE, TOO.
[CUTLER CHUCKLES]
T'POL: WHY DIDN'T YOU
LET THEM FINISH TREATING YOU
ON THE SURFACE?
TRAVIS: HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
TO AN ALIEN HOSPITAL?
T'POL: YES.
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
TRAVIS: THESE PEOPLE HAVE NEVER
TREATED A HUMAN BEFORE.
I WANTED MY OWN DOCTOR.
WHERE'S PHLOX?
CUTLER: HE'S NOT AVAILABLE.
TRAVIS: WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
HE'S NOT AVAILABLE?
CUTLER: HE'S SLEEPING.
TRAVIS: WELL, WAKE HIM UP!
HE'S GOT A PATIENT.
T'POL: THE DOCTOR
IS HIBERNATING.
TRAVIS: HIBERNATING?
FOR HOW LONG?
CUTLER: JUST A COUPLE OF DAYS.
[TRAVIS SIGHS]
CUTLER: DON'T WORRY.
I CAN HANDLE A BROKEN LEG.
HE SAID HE WAS
HAVING TROUBLE BREATHING
WHEN WE WERE IN THE POD.
CUTLER: DID THEY GIVE YOU
ANY MEDICATION?
TRAVIS: JUST A HYPOSPRAY
FOR THE PAIN.
CUTLER: HMM.
TRAVIS: IS SOMETHING WRONG?
CUTLER:
AH, IT'S PROBABLY NOTHING.
LET'S GET YOU TO SICK BAY.
[TUCKER YELPS]
[GRUNTING]
REED: GOOD MORNING.
TUCKER: I DON'T KNOW IF IT WAS
THOSE RISAN MAI TAIS...
OR GETTING SHOT,
BUT MY HEAD'S KILLING ME.
REED: IT WAS PROBABLY BOTH.
THE SUN'S UP.
WE'VE BEEN DOWN HERE ALL NIGHT.
TUCKER: GREAT.
OUR SHORE LEAVE'S HALF OVER.
HEY! WE NEED SOME HELP
DOWN HERE!
HELLO!
REED: I ALREADY TRIED IT.
CLUB'S CLOSED.
TUCKER: I DON'T PLAN ON
SPENDING OUR ENTIRE TRIP
TIED UP IN A BASEMENT.
REED: THE VULCAN DATABASE DIDN'T
MENTION ANYTHING ABOUT CRIME.
TUCKER: WELL, THEY SAID
IT WAS VERY RARE.
REED: WHAT?
TUCKER: IT HAD SOME WARNINGS,
BUT I DIDN'T THINK
IT'D BE A PROBLEM.
REED: WONDERFUL.
TUCKER: YOU THINK
THIS IS MY FAULT!
REED: YOU WERE WILLING TO FOLLOW
2 STRANGE ALIENS
INTO A BASEMENT.
TUCKER: GORGEOUS ALIENS.
DON'T FORGET THEY WERE GORGEOUS.
REED: THEY WERE MALE!
TUCKER: NOT AT FIRST!
I DON'T
REMEMBER TWISTING YOUR ARM.
REED: IF WE DON'T MAKE
IT TO THE LANDING ZONE ON TIME,
THEY'RE GOING TO START SCANNING
FOR OUR BIOSIGNS.
DO YOU WANT THE CAPTAIN
TO FIND US LIKE THIS?
[MEN GRUNTING]
OH.
I FEEL TERRIBLE.
CUTLER:
OH, YOU'RE HAVING A REACTION
TO THE PAINKILLER THEY GAVE YOU.
T'POL: WHAT'S HIS CONDITION?
CUTLER: IF THE SWELLING
GETS ANY WORSE,
IT COULD BEGIN
TO CONSTRICT HIS AIRWAY.
T'POL: I'VE SPOKEN
TO THE HOSPITAL.
THEY'VE NEVER HEARD
OF A REACTION LIKE THIS,
BUT THEY'RE NOT FAMILIAR
WITH HUMAN PHYSIOLOGY.
I REALLY THINK
WE SHOULD WAKE UP DR. PHLOX.
[RAVIS SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
HOSHI: I'M SORRY.
I GIVE UP.
I NEVER THOUGHT THAT I'D HEAR
A LANGUAGE I COULDN'T LEARN.
RAVIS: DON'T FEEL BAD.
YOU'VE ONLY BEEN TRYING
FOR ONE DAY.
HOSHI: OH, IT ONLY TOOK YOU
ONE DAY TO PICK UP ENGLISH.
RAVIS: IT IS MUCH SIMPLER.
AND YOU ARE A VERY GOOD...
PREEMARI.
HOSHI: TEACHER.
RAVIS: WHAT DO YOU CALL THIS?
HOSHI: OH, WE DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING EXACTLY LIKE IT.
THE CLOSEST THING WOULD BE
A STRAWBERRY.
RAVIS: STRAWBERRY.
HOSHI: MM-HMM.
RAVIS: AND THIS?
HOSHI: UM...IT TASTES
LIKE A KIWI.
WHAT?
IN MY LANGUAGE,
"KEE'HWI" IS, UM...
HOSHI: WHAT?
RAVIS: I DON'T KNOW THE WORD.
MAY I SHOW YOU?
HOSHI: SURE. WHY NOT?
RAVIS: KEE'HWI.
HOSHI: KISS.
THAT'S CALLED A KISS.
RAVIS: A KISS.
THERE'S A PLACE
I WAS PLANNING TO GO TODAY.
A STEAM POOL.
THEY SAY IT'S VERY...
RELAXING.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO GO?
HOSHI:
AVEC PLAISIR. THAT'S FRENCH.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
[DOOR CHIMES]
KEYLA: GOOD MORNING.
ARCHER: GOOD MORNING.
COME IN.
KEYLA: I THOUGHT WE COULD
TAKE OUR DOGS TO THE BEACH
IF YOU DON'T HAVE OTHER PLANS.
ARCHER: SOUNDS GREAT.
I JUST ORDERED BREAKFAST.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO JOIN ME?
KEYLA: CERTAINLY.
ARCHER: JUICE?
KEYLA: PLEASE.
WHAT ARE YOU READING?
ARCHER: IT'S A GIFT
FROM MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
HER PEOPLE THINK HUMANS ARE TOO
CONTROLLED BY THEIR EMOTIONS.
I KNEW THERE WAS A REASON
I LIKED YOU.
[ARCHER CHUCKLES]
ARCHER: SEEMS LIKE
YOU KNOW A LOT ABOUT ME--
WHERE I'M FROM,
WHAT BOOKS I READ.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
YOUR DOG'S NAME.
KEYLA: IT'S RHYLO.
I ADOPTED HER
WHEN SHE WAS A PUPPY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
ARCHER: EVERYTHING ELSE.
WHAT'S YOUR PLANET CALLED?
WHAT DO YOU DO?
DO YOU HAVE A FAMILY?
KEYLA: WE'VE BEEN HAVING
SUCH A WONDERFUL TIME.
I REALLY DON'T WANT TO SPOIL IT.
HOW COULD YOU SPOIL IT?
I DID HAVE A FAMILY.
THEY WERE KILLED.
MY PARENTS, MY BROTHER,
MY HUSBAND.
ARCHER: I'M SORRY.
KEYLA: IT WAS OUR OWN FAULT.
WE'D BEEN WARNED
ABOUT THE SULIBAN.
WE SHOULD HAVE GOTTEN OUT
WHILE WE HAD THE CHANCE.
SULIBAN?
YOU KNOW ABOUT THEM?
YES.
CUTLER, WHISPERING: I'M NOT
SO SURE THIS IS A GOOD IDEA.
T'POL: THERE'S NO NEED
TO WHISPER.
HE'S IN A STATE
OF DEEP HIBERNATION.
CUTLER: YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
T'POL: DID YOU USE
THE CORRECT DOSAGE?
PHLOX: DO'SANI!
DO'SANI, YO-TO ARUDA!
PHLOX?
PHLOX: I DON'T CARE
WHAT IT TASTES LIKE.
[GROANS]
T'POL: WAKE UP, DOCTOR.
SUBCOMMANDER.
HAS IT BEEN 48 HOURS?
T'POL: NO.
THEN WHY DID YOU WAKE ME?
THERE'S A MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
EMERGENCY?
THEN CALL THE DOCTOR.
T'POL: YOU'RE THE DOCTOR.
OF COURSE.
WHO'S SICK?
T'POL: ENSIGN MAYWEATHER.
PHLOX: WHO?
T'POL: ENSIGN MAYWEATHER,
OUR HELMSMAN.
I KNOW WHO HE IS. OOF.
WHERE IS HE?
CUTLER: IN SICK BAY.
PHLOX: WE'RE NOT IN SICK BAY?
T'POL: WE'RE IN YOUR QUARTERS.
PHLOX: WELL, THEN...
[GROANS]
TO SICK BAY!
I COULD USE SOME ASSISTANCE,
PLEASE.
PHLOX: WHAT SEEMS TO BE
THE TROUBLE, CAPTAIN?
IT'S TRAVIS, DOCTOR.
HE'S HAVING SOME KIND
OF ANAPHYLACTIC REACTION.
INCREDIBLE.
T'POL: WHAT?
I'VE BEEN STANDING UP
FOR ALMOST 5 MINUTES.
CUTLER: DOCTOR.
PHLOX: AH. HAND ME
THAT SCANNER, CAPTAIN.
HM-MM.
HMM.
AH, YES, YES.
[CLEARS THROAT]
UH-HUH.
IT'S DEFINITELY BEING CAUSED
BY AN ANTIGENIC COMPOUND
IN HIS SYSTEM.
WE'LL NEED REGULAN BLOODWORMS.
TRAVIS: WHAT?!
PHLOX: THEY'RE EXCELLENT
AT FILTERING TOXINS.
CUTLER: UH, WHICH CONTAINER ARE
THEY IN?
PHLOX: NO! FRESH ONES
WOULD BE BETTER.
SET A COURSE FOR REGULUS,
MAXIMUM WARP.
T'POL: DOCTOR, I THINK
THIS WAS A MISTAKE.
YOU SHOULD RETURN
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
PHLOX: I APPRECIATE THE OFFER,
BUT IT WOULD BE BEST
TO KEEP OUR RELATIONSHIP
PROFESSIONAL.
CUTLER: UGH! LET'S GO, DOCTOR.
PHLOX: I AM THE CHIEF MEDICAL
OFFICER ON THIS SHIP,
AND I AM GOING TO TREAT
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER.
AND THEN I'M GOING BACK TO BED.
HMM.
THIS WAS WAITING FOR ME
WHEN I CHECKED IN,
COMPLIMENTS OF THE MANAGEMENT.
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT RISAN VINTAGES,
BUT WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE THROW CAUTION TO THE WIND
AND GIVE IT A TRY?
I'LL BE ADVENTUROUS IF YOU WILL.
ARCHER: HOW'S YOUR ANKLE?
KEYLA: MM, IT'S GETTING BETTER.
ARCHER: YOU'D THINK THAT GUIDE
WOULD HAVE WARNED US.
KEYLA: THE WATER
WAS VERY SHALLOW.
I SHOULD HAVE WATCHED
WHERE I WAS STEPPING.
ARCHER: I DON'T KNOW.
THAT THING WAS
PRETTY WELL CAMOUFLAGED.
TO RISAN SEA TURTLES?
KEYLA: IT'S A LITTLE
SWEET FOR MY TASTE.
[KEYLA SIGHS]
ARCHER: IS SOMETHING WRONG?
KEYLA: CAMOUFLAGED.
WE COULD ONLY SEE THEM
WHEN THEY MOVED.
ARCHER: WAS THERE MORE THAN ONE?
KEYLA: I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT TURTLES.
YOU SAID YOU KNEW WHO THEY WERE.
HAVE YOU SEEN THEM?
DID THEY HURT ANYONE
THAT YOU CARED ABOUT?
ARCHER: WE'VE SEEN THEM A NUMBER
OF TIMES, BUT WE'VE BEEN LUCKY.
NO ONE WAS BADLY HURT.
KEYLA: HOW DO YOU FIGHT
SOMETHING YOU CAN'T EVEN SEE?
I WAS TOLD THAT THEY TAKE
THEIR ORDERS FROM THE FUTURE.
ARCHER: IS THAT RIGHT?
KEYLA: ALL THEIR
GENETIC ENHANCEMENTS--
THEY WERE TAUGHT TO DO THAT BY
SOMEONE FROM THE DISTANT FUTURE.
ARCHER: WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
KEYLA: IT'S NO SECRET.
THEY'VE ATTACKED
DOZENS OF SHIPS, SETTLEMENTS.
BUT WHERE DO THEY COME FROM?
WHERE DO THEY LIVE?
ARCHER: I WISH I COULD TELL YOU,
BUT I DON'T KNOW.
KEYLA: WHAT ARE THEY PLANNING
TO DO NEXT?
ARCHER: HOPEFULLY, NEITHER OF US
WILL EVER RUN INTO THEM AGAIN.
KEYLA: YOU KNOW THAT ISN'T TRUE.
THEY KEEP ENLISTING
MORE OF THEIR PEOPLE INTO THE...
WHAT DO THEY CALL IT?
THE CABAL.
YOU MUST KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT THEM, JONATHAN.
ARCHER: I REALIZE THAT
THEY MURDERED YOUR FAMILY,
AND I'M VERY SORRY FOR THAT,
BUT I'M NOT SURE
WHAT YOU WANT ME TO TELL YOU.
MOST OF WHAT I HAVE LEARNED
ABOUT THEM
HAS COME FROM RUMORS
AND HEARSAY,
BUT YOU HAVE SEEN THEM
FACE-TO-FACE.
I WANT YOU TO TELL ME
WHAT YOU KNOW.
WHERE ARE THEIR HELIXES?
WHERE DO THEY LIVE?!
IF THIS WINE IS TOO SWEET,
I THINK
THERE'S ANOTHER BOTTLE HERE.
IT MIGHT BE DIFFERENT.
KEYLA: YOU'RE THE FIRST PERSON
I'VE MET IN OVER A YEAR
WHO'S HAD ANY CONTACT WITH THEM.
ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW MUCH,
BUT I'LL TELL YOU WHAT I CAN.
I COULD USE SOME FRESH AIR.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE A WALK
ON THE BEACH?
KEYLA: THANK YOU.
ARCHER: IT'S KIND OF CHILLY.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO GO GET
A SWEATER OR SOMETHING.
KEYLA: I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER: ARCHER TO "ENTERPRISE."
T'POL: THIS IS T'POL.
ARCHER: I'M TRANSMITTING
A BIOSCAN TO YOU.
RUN IT THROUGH THE COMPUTER.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND A MATCH.
T'POL: YOU DON'T SOUND
VERY RELAXED, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: QUICKLY, PLEASE.
T'POL: UNDERSTOOD.
[DOOR CHIMES]
KEYLA: READY?
ARCHER: NOT QUITE.
YOUR SURGEONS DID A NICE JOB.
ALL THE TANDARANS I MET
HAD A VERY DISTINCTIVE
FEATURE RIGHT HERE.
KEYLA: TANDARANS?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: I TOOK A BIOSCAN.
THEY MAY BE ABLE
TO CHANGE YOUR FACE,
BUT NOT YOUR DNA.
DID COLONEL GRAT SEND YOU?
KEYLA: WHO?
ARCHER: I SUPPOSE IT'S POSSIBLE
YOU DON'T KNOW HIM.
HE RAN THE DETENTION CAMP
I WAS SENT TO.
IT WAS FILLED
WITH INNOCENT SULIBAN.
GRAT ASKED ME THE SAME QUESTIONS
YOU'VE BEEN ASKING,
EXCEPT HE WAS
A LITTLE MORE AGGRESSIVE.
ON THE OTHER HAND, HE DIDN'T TRY
TO WIN MY SYMPATHY
WITH FICTITIOUS TRAGEDIES.
KEYLA: YOU'RE WRONG, JONATHAN.
YOU'RE ALL WRONG.
I THINK I SHOULD LEAVE.
ARCHER: IF IT WASN'T GRAT,
THEN WHO WAS IT?
WHO SENT YOU HERE?
WHO WAS IT?!
KEYLA: I'M SORRY.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY KIND TO ME.
I'M GOING TO CHECK OUT NOW.
I CAN'T HAVE YOU INTERFERING.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
REED: WHATEVER WAS IN
THAT BOTTLE YOU BROKE
GOT ALL OVER ME.
IT STINKS TO HIGH HEAVEN.
TUCKER: IT'S NOT LIKE
I HAD A CHOICE.
WE NEEDED SOMETHING
TO CUT THROUGH THOSE ROPES.
[MALE CHUCKLES]
RAVIS: GOOD MORNING.
HOSHI: GOOD MORNING.
RAVIS: SLEEP WELL?
HOSHI: VERY.
RAVIS: ANY THOUGHTS ABOUT
WHAT YOU'D LIKE TO DO TODAY?
RISA HAS A LOT TO OFFER.
HOSHI: I COULD SPEND
THE ENTIRE DAY RIGHT HERE,
BUT I'M AFRAID THE SHUTTLE'S
COMING TO PICK ME UP
IN A FEW HOURS.
RAVIS: NOT A VERY LONG VACATION.
HOSHI: TWO DAYS AND TWO NIGHTS.
THAT'S ALL WE HAD.
RAVIS: I HOPE YOU DON'T
THINK THAT I...
HOSHI: TOOK ADVANTAGE OF ME?
NOT FOR A MINUTE.
PHLOX: THERE WE GO.
T'POL: YOU'RE CERTAIN?
PHLOX: YOU CAN CHECK IT YOURSELF
IF YOU LIKE, DOCTOR.
THE ANALYSIS CLEARLY SHOWS HE
WAS GIVEN BENZETHONIUM CHLORIDE.
YOU'RE QUITE ALLERGIC TO IT.
THIS SHOULD DO THE TRICK.
T'POL: YOUR BIOSIGNS
ARE STABILIZING.
IT SEEMS TO BE WORKING.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
A LOT BETTER.
THANKS, DOC.
[PHLOX SNORING]
[ARCHER GROANING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
WHAT'S THAT SMELL?
REED: I DON'T SMELL ANYTHING.
ARCHER: I'M GUESSING YOU TWO HAD
AN INTERESTING COUPLE OF DAYS.
TUCKER: FASCINATING
CULTURE, SIR.
ARCHER: MM-HMM.
TUCKER: WHAT ABOUT YOU, HOSHI?
DO ANYTHING CONSTRUCTIVE?
AS A MATTER OF FACT, I LEARNED
SEVERAL NEW CONJUGATIONS.
TUCKER: HMM.
REED: YOU LOOK RESTED, SIR.
DID YOU GET
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP?
ARCHER:
WENT OUT LIKE A LIGHT.
TUCKER:
NEXT TIME WE TAKE SHORE LEAVE,
INSTEAD OF JUST SITTING AROUND
READING BOOKS,
YOU SHOULD TRY TO GET OUT.
LOOK FOR A LITTLE EXCITEMENT.
MEET NEW PEOPLE.