ARCHER: THEY DON'T HAVE
A PROBLEM WITH US DROPPING BY?
T'POL: ON THE CONTRARY.
THE OPERATIONS FOREMAN SAID
THEY HAVEN'T HAD VISITORS
IN NEARLY 6 MONTHS.
TUCKER: IS IT REALLY
A MATRIARCHAL SOCIETY?
I MEAN, THE WOMEN
MAKE ALL THE DECISIONS?
T'POL: UNTIL RECENTLY.
BUT IN THE LAST DECADE,
THE PARAAGAN MALES
HAVE MADE GREAT STRIDES
TO ACQUIRE EQUAL RIGHTS.
TUCKER: STILL, IT WOULD
PROBABLY BE BEST
IF WE DIDN'T GET
TOO FLIRTATIOUS.
ARCHER: PROBABLY.
I READ THAT THIS COLONY
STARTED OFF 20 YEARS AGO
WITH JUST 30 MINERS.
NOW THERE ARE OVER 3,000.
THEY'VE GOT SCHOOLS,
LANDSCAPED COMMUNITIES,
EVEN SOME KIND OF MUSEUM.
TUCKER: YOU THINK,
20 YEARS FROM NOW,
THERE'LL BE EARTH COLONIES
OUT THIS FAR?
HUMAN KIDS GROWING UP
ON NEW SAUSALITO?
HUH. IF MY FATHER WERE ALIVE,
HE WOULDN'T DOUBT IT
FOR A MINUTE.
WE'RE MAKING HISTORY WITH...
ARCHER: EVERY LIGHT-YEAR.
TUCKER: EVERY LIGHT-YEAR.
YOU KNOW, I THINK I'VE HEARD
YOU SAY THAT
AT LEAST HALF A DOZEN TIMES.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
ARCHER HERE.
TRAVIS: THE PARAAGANS HAVE GIVEN
US CLEARANCE TO ENTER ORBIT.
T'POL: HAVE YOU RECEIVED
THEIR LANDING PROTOCOLS?
TRAVIS: THEY'RE COMING IN NOW.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
THIS SHOULD TAKE
A BIT LONGER THAN USUAL.
ARCHER: IT WOULDN'T
BE VERY POLITE
TO IGNITE THEIR ATMOSPHERE.
WHEN ARE YOU SUPPOSED TO CLOSE
THE PLASMA DUCTS?
REED: THE PROTOCOL
SAID 50 KILOMETERS.
BUT TO BE ON THE SAFE SIDE,
I'M GONNA LOCK THEM OFF
AT ABOUT 75.
T'POL: ALTHOUGH
THE MATRIARCHAL ELEMENTS
OF THE CULTURE HAVE DIMINISHED,
IT MIGHT BE BEST
IF I WERE TO ASK--
[EXPLOSIONS]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
REED: I CLOSED BOTH
PLASMA DUCTS. I'M CERTAIN OF IT.
ARCHER: ARE YOU SURE
THERE'S NOTHING LEFT?
HOSHI: WE COULD SEE THE COLONY
IN FULL MAGNIFICATION, SIR.
THE GROUND WAS SCORCHED FOR
AT LEAST A HUNDRED KILOMETERS
IN EVERY DIRECTION.
COULD ONE OF THE DAMPENERS
BEEN MALFUNCTIONING?
REED: I CLOSED BOTH DUCTS.
ANY KIND OF MALFUNCTION
WOULD HAVE TRIGGERED AN ALARM.
TWO ALARMS.
THERE ARE BACKUPS TO PREVENT
THESE KINDS OF ACCIDENTS.
THE DUCTS WERE CLOSED.
T'POL: THIS IS NO TIME
TO BE PLACING BLAME.
A THOROUGH INVESTIGATION SHOULD
EXPLAIN WHAT HAPPENED.
HOW IS HE?
PHLOX: HE HAS A MILD CONCUSSION,
BUT HE SHOULD BE FINE.
ARCHER: HAVE YOU TRIED
HAILING THE COLONY?
THERE HAS TO BE
SOMEONE DOWN THERE.
HOSHI: SIR, I TRIED TO EXPLAIN.
THERE'S NOTHING LEFT.
NO BUILDINGS,
NO TREES, NO PEOPLE.
ARCHER: THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE WERE 3,600 COLONISTS.
ARCHER: HAVE YOU FINISHED
THE DIAGNOSTICS?
T'POL: I'VE ANALYZED
6 OF THE POD SENSOR LOGS.
I HAVE TWO LEFT.
ARCHER: WELL, GET THEM DONE.
YOU'VE HAD 3 HOURS.
WHAT ABOUT THE "ENTERPRISE"
SENSOR LOGS?
THEY MUST HAVE RECORDED HOW MUCH
TETRAZINE WAS IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
WAS THE CONCENTRATION GREATER
THAN THE PARAAGANS SPECIFIED?
WAS IT PRESENT
AT HIGHER ALTITUDES
THAN IT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE?
TUCKER: THAT'S
THE WEIRD PART, SIR.
THE TETRAZINE LEVELS WERE
LESS THAN 3 PARTS PER MILLION.
THAT'S HALF
WHAT THE PROTOCOL SPECIFIED.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT
THE POINT OF IGNITION?
REED: THE FLASH POINT WAS
DIRECTLY
BENEATH THE SHUTTLE, SIR.
BUT IT SEEMS TO HAVE ORIGINATED
AT THE STARBOARD PLASMA DUCT.
ARCHER: A PLASMA DUCT
YOU'RE CERTAIN WAS CLOSED.
T'POL: EVERY LOG
ON THE SHUTTLE INDICATES
THAT BOTH DUCTS
WERE SEALED AND LOCKED.
ARCHER: THEN YOU'D BETTER START
REEXAMINING THOSE LOGS.
BECAUSE SOMETHING
DOESN'T ADD UP HERE.
GET ME ADMIRAL FORREST.
THIS IS NOT GONNA BE FUN.
TETRAZINE?
ARCHER: IT'S A BY-PRODUCT
OF THEIR MINING OPERATION.
IT SETTLES BETWEEN 45 AND 50
KILOMETERS IN THEIR ATMOSPHERE.
EXHAUST PLASMA IS ABOUT THE ONLY
THING HOT ENOUGH TO IGNITE IT.
BUT YOU SAID YOUR PLASMA DUCTS
WERE CLOSED.
ARCHER: YES, SIR.
WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO DETERMINE WHAT WENT WRONG.
BUT THAT'S
NOT GONNA CHANGE THE FACT
THAT THERE ARE 3,600 CORPSES
DOWN THERE.
CONTINUE TO ANALYZE YOUR LOGS.
I'M GOING TO CALL
AN EMERGENCY MEETING
OF THE COMMAND COUNCIL.
YOU REALIZE THEY'LL UNDOUBTEDLY
BRING THE VULCANS INTO THIS.
WE'LL HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
WHO'S GOING TO CONTACT
THE PARAAGAN HOMEWORLD.
THAT SHOULD BE
MY RESPONSIBILITY, SIR.
YOU'RE RIGHT. IT SHOULD.
BUT LET'S TAKE THIS
ONE STEP AT A TIME.
HOW DO YOU TELL
ALL THOSE FAMILIES THAT...
YOU FOLLOWED ALL THE PROTOCOLS
THAT YOU WERE GIVEN.
WE CAME HERE
TO MEET THESE PEOPLE,
TO LEARN SOMETHING ABOUT THEM,
NOT TO KILL THEM.
YOU FOLLOWED THE PROTOCOLS.
YOU'VE GOT A CREW THAT'S
GOING TO BE LOOKING TO YOU
TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO REACT TO ALL THIS.
DON'T LET THEM DOWN.
I'LL GET BACK TO YOU
AS SOON AS I CAN.
I'M SORRY, JON.
HIS BEHAVIOR HAS BEEN ERRATIC.
HE SEEMS TO ALTERNATE
BETWEEN AGITATION,
DESPONDENCY, AND GUILT.
HE SPENDS
MOST OF HIS TIME ALONE.
I'VE TRIED TO REMIND HIM
THAT THIS WAS AN ACCIDENT,
BUT HIS RESPONSES
HAVE BEEN ILLOGICAL.
HE SEEMS TO BE IGNORING HIS
RESPONSIBILITIES AS CAPTAIN.
PHLOX: AH, TO BE VULCAN.
IT'S BEEN MY EXPERIENCE
THAT HUMANS
HAVE A GREAT DEAL OF DIFFICULTY
SEPARATING EMOTIONAL DESPAIR
FROM WHAT YOU CALL
RESPONSIBILITY.
T'POL:
NEVERTHELESS, AS HIS PHYSICIAN,
YOU SHOULD MONITOR HIM CLOSELY
TO BE CERTAIN HE REMAINS FIT
FOR COMMAND.
PHLOX: I UNDERSTAND
HOW, UM, UNCOMFORTABLE
HIS BEHAVIOR MUST BE
FOR YOU, BUT...
TRUST ME.
IT WOULD BE UNNATURAL
FOR THE CAPTAIN
NOT TO BE AFFECTED BY GRIEF
UNDER THESE CIRCUMSTANCES.
IT'S, UH, HUMAN NATURE.
HE'LL BE FINE.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
WHAT IS IT?
HOSHI:
IT'S ADMIRAL FORREST, SIR.
THANK YOU.
[SIGHS]
THE ATMOSPHERIC ANALYSIS
OF THE PROBE IS COMING THROUGH.
REED: PUT IT UP HERE, WOULD YOU?
WHAT IS IT?
REED: THE AIR NEAR
THE SURFACE IS FILLED
WITH TRACES OF BOROCARBONS.
TUCKER: WHEN TETRAZINE IS
IGNITED BY PLASMA EXHAUST,
THERE'S ONLY ONE OUTCOME
YOU CAN BE SURE OF.
TRACES OF BOROCARBONS.
TUCKER: YOU GOT IT.
REED: I DON'T CARE
WHETHER THAT PROBE
PICKED UP TRACES
OF BREAD PUDDING.
BOTH OUR PLASMA DUCTS
WERE LOCKED DOWN
AND THERE WERE NO LEAKS
IN THE SYSTEM,
NOT UNLESS THEY MIRACULOUSLY
MENDED THEMSELVES AFTERWARDS.
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER: T'POL.
TRIP.
THE MISSION'S BEEN CANCELED.
TUCKER: CANCELED?!
FROM WHAT THE ADMIRAL TELLS ME,
AMBASSADOR SOVAL WILL USE
THIS TO CONVINCE STARFLEET...
THAT WE NEED ANOTHER
10 OR 20 YEARS
BEFORE WE TRY THIS AGAIN.
TUCKER: 20 YEARS?!
STARFLEET WON'T BUY THAT
FOR A MINUTE.
ARCHER: WON'T THEY?
TUCKER: TELL HIM HE'S CRAZY!
TELL HIM THAT'S GUILT TALKING,
NOT JONATHAN ARCHER!
ARCHER: A VULCAN SHIP WILL
MEET US IN 3 DAYS
TO GET YOU AND DR. PHLOX.
PLEASE INFORM MR. MAYWEATHER
TO HEAD FOR THESE COORDINATES.
TUCKER: I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE
LETTING THEM DO THIS TO US.
YOU'VE WAITED ALL YOUR LIFE
TO COMMAND THIS SHIP.
DISMISSED.
TUCKER: BUT, SIR--
ARCHER: I SAID YOU'RE DISMISSED.
BOTH OF YOU.
TRAVIS: YOU THINK THEY'VE
REPLACED YOU IN BRAZIL YET?
HOSHI: EVEN IF THEY HAVE,
THEY'D TAKE ME BACK.
I'M A PRODIGY, REMEMBER?
HOW ABOUT YOU?
TRAVIS: AFTER A YEAR
ON "ENTERPRISE,"
THE THOUGHT OF A CARGO SHIP
IS PRETTY UNAPPEALING.
HOSHI: WHAT IF THEY
MADE YOU CAPTAIN?
YOU'RE GONNA BE THE MOST FAMOUS
BOOMER AROUND, YOU KNOW?
[TRAVIS SIGHS]
OR MAYBE INFAMOUS.
FROM WHAT COMMANDER TUCKER
TELLS ME,
PEOPLE BACK HOME THINK THAT
WE'RE DOING NOTHING OUT
HERE BUT GETTING IN TROUBLE.
HOSHI: THEN IT'S OUR JOB
TO LET THE PEOPLE BACK HOME
KNOW WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
ANYONE TRIES TO BAD-MOUTH
CAPTAIN ARCHER IN FRONT OF
ME IS GONNA GET AN EARFUL
IN ANY LANGUAGE THEY WANT.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
WHAT WAS SO IMPORTANT
IT COULDN'T WAIT TILL MORNING?
T'POL: IF YOU'D PREFER,
I'LL COME BACK.
NO, I'M SORRY.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
LIEUTENANT REED AND HIS TEAM
HAVE DISCOVERED
AN UNIDENTIFIED E.M. SIGNATURE
ON THE VENTRAL HULL
OF SHUTTLEPOD 1.
COULD BE ANYTHING.
T'POL: MR. REED FELT
YOU'D BE INTERESTED.
ARCHER: IN WHAT?
DOES HE THINK THAT
STARFLEET COMMAND'S
GONNA TAKE A LOOK AT THIS,
APOLOGIZE,
AND SEND US ON OUR WAY?
TELL HIM IT WAS A NICE TRY.
T'POL: IS THIS WHAT
HUMANS REFER TO AS
"FEELING SORRY FOR THEMSELVES"?
ARCHER: YOU'RE OUT OF LINE,
SUBCOMMANDER.
T'POL: I APOLOGIZE.
ARCHER: I WISH I WAS SIMPLY
FEELING SORRY FOR MYSELF.
BUT ACTUALLY I'M FEELING
SORRY FOR A WHOLE LOT OF PEOPLE.
EVERY MEMBER OF STARFLEET,
IN FACT.
THEIR FUTURES DEPENDED UPON
MY ABILITY
TO SUCCEED AT THIS MISSION.
AS SOON AS WE LEARNED ABOUT
THE CONSEQUENCES
OF THE EXPLOSION,
I KNEW THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
WOULD TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF THE SITUATION.
ARCHER: WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
YOU HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
TO DISPUTE THEIR RECOMMENDATION.
ARCHER: STARFLEET ALREADY BOUGHT
THEIR RECOMMENDATION
HOOK, LINE, AND SINKER.
T'POL:
THEN YOU HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
TO CONVINCE THEM AS WELL.
ARCHER: AND HOW DO YOU SUGGEST
I DO THAT?
T'POL: YOU ARE VERY ADEPT
AT LISTING THE QUESTIONABLE
DECISIONS YOU'VE MADE.
BUT THERE HAVE BEEN
OTHER DECISIONS--
MANY OF THEM--
THAT NO ONE WOULD QUESTION.
I'M WILLING TO TRY TO CONVINCE
MY GOVERNMENT OF THAT.
ARE YOU WILLING TO TRY
TO CONVINCE YOURS?
YOU KNOW...
THIS HAS GOT TO BE
THE FIRST TIME A VULCAN
HAS EVER ATTEMPTED
TO CHEER UP A HUMAN.
I'LL SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
[CREATURE CHATTERS]
THAT'S ALL RIGHT, COMMANDER.
YOUR COMPANY IS APPRECIATED,
BUT IT WOULD BE BEST
IF YOU LEFT THE PACKING TO ME.
TUCKER: I WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
YOU'D BE A LITTLE MORE UPSET
ABOUT LEAVING "ENTERPRISE."
PHLOX: WELL, I, UH--
I DID EXPECT THIS POSTING
WOULD LAST A WHILE LONGER,
BUT I'M SURE AN EQUALLY
ADVENTUROUS OPPORTUNITY
WILL PRESENT ITSELF.
TUCKER: I WISH
I HAD YOUR ATTITUDE.
PHLOX: HUMANS SEEM TO BE
NATURALLY OPTIMISTIC.
I'M SURPRISED YOU DON'T
SHARE MY OUTLOOK--
THAT SOMETHING EXCITING'S
ALWAYS WAITING
AROUND THE NEXT NEBULA.
TUCKER: THAT'S JUST THE POINT.
THERE WON'T BE ANY NEBULAS
IN STARFLEET'S FUTURE.
AT LEAST NOT FOR A DECADE OR SO.
PHLOX: OH, I WOULDN'T
BE SO SURE OF THAT.
YOU'RE WRONG, DOC.
YOU WORKED WITH VULCANS.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY THINK OF US.
"ENTERPRISE"
COMING BACK TO EARTH
WITH ITS TAIL TUCKED
BETWEEN ITS LEGS.
IT'LL BE SOVAL'S
CROWNING ACHIEVEMENT.
THEY'LL PROBABLY GIVE THE SON OF
A BITCH SOME GAUDY MEDAL
AND THEN CART HIM OFF
TO WHEREVER THEY SEND
BITTER OLD VULCANS TO RETIRE.
PHLOX: AMBASSADOR SOVAL'S
SERVICE RECORD
CONTAINS AN IMPRESSIVE LIST
OF ACCOMPLISHMENTS.
TUCKER: YOU HAVE TO FIND
SOMETHING GOOD
IN EVERYBODY, DON'T YOU?
I GOT TO TELL YOU, THAT'S ONE OF
YOUR UNIQUE QUALITIES
THAT DRIVES ME CRAZY.
PHLOX: I'LL CERTAINLY MISS
YOUR OUTSPOKEN PERSONALITY,
MR. TUCKER.
TUCKER: I'LL SEE YOU LATER, DOC.
COME ON, PORTHOS.
TIME FOR BED.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
PORTHOS, UP.
[PAT PAT]
WHAT'S THE MATTER, BOY?
DON'T TELL ME YOU'RE....
PORTHOS?
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
[BEEPING]
HELLO?
TUCKER: SORRY
TO CALL SO LATE, CAPTAIN,
BUT ALL 3 INSPECTION PODS
ARE GETTING THEIR
WEEKLY OVERHAULS TONIGHT.
THEY TELL ME
THEY WON'T BE READY UNTIL NOON.
SO I FIGURED...
BOTH: YOU MIGHT WANT
TO SLEEP IN.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU SAY
TO BREAKFAST AT 9:30,
SPACEDOCK CAFETERIA?
TUCKER: YOU MUST BE
READING MY MIND.
I WAS JUST ABOUT TO SUGGEST
THE SAME THING.
ARCHER: SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
IF YOU'RE TRYING TO TELL ME THE
LAST 10 MONTHS WAS A DREAM...
I'M NOT BUYING IT.
I.M.E. CAN I HELP YOU?
THIS IS CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER,
STARFLEET AUTHORIZATION
ALPHA-SIX-FOUR--
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE, CAPTAIN.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
DO YOU HAVE A DENOBULAN DOCTOR
IN THE INTERSPECIES
MEDICAL EXCHANGE?
YES. A DR. PHLOX.
HE'S ASSIGNED TO STARFLEET
MEDICAL HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO CONTACT HIM FOR YOU?
NO, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW PHLOX EXISTED
BEFORE THEY BROUGHT KLAANG IN.
AND THAT WAS THE DAY
AFTER THE LATE-NIGHT
CALL FROM TRIP.
MAN: YOU'RE NOT
DREAMING, CAPTAIN.
DANIELS.
THIS MUST BE VERY DISORIENTING.
I APOLOGIZE.
BUT I HAD NO CHOICE.
ARCHER: COMMANDER TUCKER TOLD ME
YOU WERE DEAD,
THAT SILIK KILLED YOU.
HE DID.
IN A MANNER OF SPEAKING.
WE HAVE TO TALK, CAPTAIN,
AND IT'S ESSENTIAL
THAT NONE OF THE OTHER FACTIONS
KNOW ABOUT IT.
I DOUBT ANY OF THEM WOULD THINK
I'D BRING YOU HERE.
ARCHER: SO YOU'RE
TELLING ME YOU...
BROUGHT ME BACK, WHAT,
10 MONTHS AGO?
HOW ABOUT JONATHAN ARCHER
10 MONTHS AGO? WHERE'S HE?
HE'S YOU.
THEN WHO JUST CLIMBED INTO BED
ABOARD "ENTERPRISE"?
THAT HASN'T HAPPENED YET.
THAT'S A LOAD OF CRAP,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
I'VE HAD THIS CONVERSATION
WITH HALF A DOZEN PEOPLE.
IT ALWAYS ENDS UP THE SAME WAY.
ARCHER: CAN'T YOU EVER
GIVE A STRAIGHT ANSWER?
IT DEPENDS ON THE QUESTION.
ARCHER: ALL RIGHT.
TRY THIS ONE.
WHY AM I HERE?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO
PROTECT THE TIMELINE,
NOT SCREW WITH IT.
IT'S ALREADY BEEN
"SCREWED WITH," CAPTAIN.
THAT EXPLOSION
AT THE PARAAGAN COLONY,
IT WASN'T SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN.
ARCHER: OF COURSE IT WASN'T.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
DANIELS: THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEAN.
HISTORY NEVER RECORDED
THE DISASTER.
SOMEONE
VIOLATED THE TEMPORAL ACCORD--
SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T WANT
YOUR MISSION TO SUCCEED.
ARE YOU TELLING ME
THAT "ENTERPRISE"
DIDN'T CAUSE THAT EXPLOSION?
DANIELS: DO YOU REMEMBER THE
TEMPORAL COLD WAR I SPOKE OF?
ARCHER:
IT'S KIND OF HARD TO FORGET.
DANIELS:
THEN LISTEN TO ME CAREFULLY.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
ALL SENIOR STAFF REPORT TO THE
SITUATION ROOM IN 15 MINUTES.
MR. REED, I'D LIKE YOU
IN MY QUARTERS IMMEDIATELY.
REED: IT WAS JUST WHERE
WE DETECTED THE E.M. SIGNATURE.
BUT I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IT WAS COMPLETELY INVISIBLE.
HOW ON EARTH DID YOU KNOW
THAT A PHASE DISCRIMINATOR
WOULD EXPOSE IT?
ARCHER: IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
YOU'LL FIND
THIS THING WAS DESIGNED
TO GENERATE A PLASMA STREAM.
PUT A TEAM TOGETHER, TRIP.
I'LL NEED TWO QUANTUM BEACONS.
THEY'LL HAVE TO BE
POSITRON-BASED
AND HAVE AN OUTPUT
OF 200 GIGAWATTS APIECE.
TUCKER: POSITRON-BASED, SIR?
ARCHER: JUST GET STARTED.
I'LL BRING YOU THE SPECS
IN A FEW MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA NEED
OUR COM FREQUENCIES
ON THE FRITZ FOR A DAY OR SO.
ARCHER: SEE TO IT.
HOSHI: AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: PUT THE ARMORY
ON FULL ALERT.
TURN THE SHIP AROUND, TRAVIS.
WE'RE GOING BACK TO
THE PARAAGAN COLONY.
WHAT ARE YOU ALL WAITING FOR?
TUCKER: SIR?
ARCHER: IT WASN'T US, TRIP.
WE DIDN'T DO IT.
[TUCKER SIGHS]
ARCHER: TAKE A LOOK AT THE
DISPERSAL CURVE HERE AND HERE.
YOU'LL HAVE TO ISOLATE
THE SUBASSEMBLY TOLERANCES
FROM THE EMITTER ALGORITHMS.
TUCKER: WHOA. HOLD ON A MINUTE.
YOU'RE SAYING THE ASSEMBLY'S
INDEPENDENT OF THE EMITTERS?
EXACTLY.
TUCKER: THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
ARCHER: NOT IF YOU
GENERATE A STABLE FLUX
BETWEEN THE POSITRON CONDUCTORS.
THEN ALL YOU'LL HAVE TO DO
IS RENORMALIZE
THE TERTIARY WAVE FUNCTIONS.
TUCKER: WITH ALL
DUE RESPECT, SIR,
THIS IS A LEVEL
OF QUANTUM ENGINEERING
THAT'S BEYOND ANYTHING
I EVER LEARNED.
HOW THE HELL DO YOU KNOW THIS?
ARCHER: REMEMBER
CREWMAN DANIELS?
TUCKER: YEAH.
I SAW HIM GET VAPORIZED
BY OUR FRIEND SILIK.
ARCHER: WELL, FOR
A CLOUD OF VAPOR,
HE'S ONE WEALTH OF INFORMATION.
I JUST SPENT TWO HOURS WITH HIM.
TUCKER: HE'S ON "ENTERPRISE"?
NOT EXACTLY.
LISTEN, I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
RIGHT NOW WE'VE GOT TO GET BACK
TO BUILDING THESE BEACONS.
TUCKER: WHATEVER YOU SAY.
ARCHER:
THE CIRCUITRY IN THERE
ISN'T COMPATIBLE
WITH OUR TECHNOLOGY.
WE'LL HAVE TO CREATE
AN INTERFACE.
HOSHI: WHAT FOR?
ARCHER: WE'RE GOING
TO BE RETRIEVING
SOME SULIBAN DATA DISCS.
I HAVE NO DOUBT YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO HANDLE THE CONTENT.
BUT BEFORE YOU CAN DO THAT,
WE'LL HAVE TO FIND A WAY
TO ACCESS THE DATA.
T'POL: AND DANIELS CLAIMS
THIS IS SULIBAN TECHNOLOGY?
ARCHER: EVERYTHING HE'S TOLD ME
HAS CHECKED OUT SO FAR.
I HAVE NO REASON
TO DOUBT HIM ON THIS.
HOSHI: WE'LL DO
OUR BEST, CAPTAIN.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
THE VULCAN SHIP
WE WERE HEADED FOR--
IT'S NO DOUBT DETECTED
WE'VE ALTERED COURSE.
HAVE THEY TRIED TO HAIL US?
HOSHI: I WOULDN'T KNOW, SIR.
OUR COM IS ON THE FRITZ.
REED: WHY DID DANIELS LEAVE IT
IN HIS QUARTERS?
ARCHER: I DON'T RECALL
HIM HAVING MUCH TIME TO PACK
BEFORE HE LEFT.
REED: NO.
WELL, IF IT IS THERE
AND IT CONTAINS
WHAT HE SAID IT DOES,
IT COULD BE INVALUABLE
TO STARFLEET.
ARCHER: I GAVE DANIELS
MY WORD, MALCOLM.
WE DOWNLOAD THE SCHEMATICS
FOR THE SULIBAN STEALTH CRUISER,
NOTHING ELSE.
REED: PITY.
ASSUMING HE'S RIGHT AND
WE MANAGE TO FIND THE CRUISER,
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THE SULIBAN WON'T COME AFTER US?
ARCHER: JUST LIKE THOSE
OLD BIBLE MOVIES, MALCOLM--
"IT WASN'T WRITTEN."
ARCHER: SO FAR, DANIELS
IS BATTING 1.000.
REED: WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU SEE THAT?
THEY'VE GOT SCHEMATICS
ON HALF A DOZEN
DIFFERENT KLINGON SHIPS.
ARCHER: THE STEALTH CRUISER,
LIEUTENANT. NOTHING ELSE.
REED: THERE. THERE IT IS.
ARCHER: TRIP?
TUCKER: I FEEL LIKE A CHEF
WHO'S JUST MADE A MEAL
WITH INGREDIENTS
HE'S NEVER TASTED.
ARCHER: YOU FOLLOW
THE INSTRUCTIONS?
TUCKER: TO THE LETTER.
T'POL: BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: WE'RE
APPROACHING THE COLONY.
ARCHER: HAVE MR. MAYWEATHER
LOCATE A BINARY SYSTEM
2.5 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY
AND SET A COURSE.
T'POL: UNDERSTOOD.
ARCHER: LET'S GET THESE MOUNTED
ON THE GRAPPLER ARMS.
ARCHER:
HEAD FOR THE SMALLER STAR,
THEN THE INNER MOON
OF THE SECOND PLANET.
BRIDGE TO ARMORY.
REED HERE.
ARCHER: HAVE YOU PLOTTED
ALL THE TARGET POINTS?
REED: AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: STAND BY.
ARCHER: I'LL MEET YOU TWO
IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
IF THIS GOES WELL,
I SHOULDN'T BE LONG.
LOWER THE BEACONS.
MODIFY THE VIEWSCREEN.
BRING UP THESE COORDINATES.
FULL MAGNIFICATION.
ACTIVATE THE BEACONS.
ARCHER: RIGHT WHERE
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE.
HOSHI: AREN'T WE IN RANGE
OF THEIR SENSORS, SIR?
ARCHER: THEY CAN SEE US.
BUT THEY HAVE NO IDEA
WE CAN SEE THROUGH THEIR CLOAK.
JUST KEEP ON
THE SAME COURSE, TRAVIS.
MALCOLM.
THE CLOSER, THE BETTER, SIR.
[ALARM]
HOSHI: THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
ARCHER: NOW, MR. REED!
CREWMAN: THEIR CLOAKING
GENERATOR'S DOWN.
REED:
ALL 4 WEAPON BANKS, AS WELL.
CREWMAN: PORT AND STARBOARD
ENGINES DISABLED.
REED: OK, HERE'S
THE TRICKY PART.
REED: REED TO SHUTTLEPOD 2.
ARCHER HERE.
REED: SHE'S ALL YOURS,
CAPTAIN. GOOD LUCK.
ARCHER: THAT LAST SHOT
SHOULD HAVE SEALED OFF
THE TWO LOWER DECKS.
IF DANIELS IS RIGHT,
THERE SHOULDN'T BE MORE THAN
20 SULIBAN FOR US TO DEAL WITH.
TUCKER: IS THAT ALL?
THE STUN GRENADE'S
ON A 3-SECOND DELAY.
REED: JUST 10 MORE METERS.
GO.
WHICH ONE?
HERE.
ARCHER: GO.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE ALL AROUND US.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO REED.
REED: GO AHEAD.
ARCHER: WE NEED SOME HELP HERE.
REED: I SEE THEM.
YOU'D BETTER TAKE COVER.
GO.
[ALARM]
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
TUCKER: I CAN'T RELEASE
THE DOCKING CLAMPS.
[THUDDING]
ARCHER: IGNITE THE THRUSTERS.
GO TO FULL POWER!
ARCHER TO MAYWEATHER.
TRAVIS: WE SEE YOU, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: SET A COURSE
BACK TOWARD THE VULCAN SHIP.
GO TO WARP 4
AS SOON AS WE'RE ABOARD.
TRAVIS: YES, SIR.
T'POL: IT TOOK AWHILE
BEFORE WE REALIZED
THAT THE 3 DISCS
HAD TO WORK IN UNISON.
THE INTERFACE SEEMS
TO BE HOLDING.
ARCHER: HOSHI?
HOSHI: THE STEALTH CRUISER
WAS DEFINITELY IN ORBIT
OF THE PARAAGAN COLONY
WHEN THE EXPLOSION TOOK PLACE.
THEY WERE MONITORING US
VERY CLOSELY.
THERE ARE SENSOR LOGS
THAT TRACKED OUR COURSE,
OUR ALTITUDE,
EVEN OUR HULL TEMPERATURE.
LOOK AT THESE.
ARCHER: I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW CLOSE THEY GOT.
T'POL: THEY GOT A LOT CLOSER
THAN YOU THINK.
HOSHI: THOSE CLOAKING DEVICES
SURE COME IN HANDY.
T'POL: THEY WERE DOCKED
WITH THE SHUTTLEPOD
FOR NEARLY TWO MINUTES.
ARCHER: JUST LONG ENOUGH
TO ATTACH THIS AND CLOAK IT.
GOOD WORK.
KEEP AT IT.
GET ME ADMIRAL FORREST.
SOUNDS LIKE
PRETTY SOLID EVIDENCE.
WHERE THE HELL DID YOU GET IT?
IT'S ALL ON 3 DATA DISCS
WE TOOK FROM A CLOAKED
SULIBAN CRUISER.
BUT HOW DID YOU KNOW
ABOUT THAT CRUISER?
AND IF IT WAS CLOAKED,
HOW COULD YOU FIND IT?
I'VE GOT FRIENDS IN HIGH PLACES.
THIS IS GOING TO BE
A VERY INTERESTING DEBRIEFING.
[CHUCKLES]
GET TO THE VULCAN SHIP
AS QUICKLY AS YOU CAN.
I'LL LET THEM KNOW
WHAT YOU'VE GOT.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW PLEASED I AM, JONATHAN.
AFTER ALL YOU'VE DONE,
I WOULD HAVE HATED
TO SEE THIS END.
THANK YOU FOR BELIEVING
IN US, ADMIRAL.
ARCHER OUT.
SILIK: THEY BOARDED
A CLOAKED VESSEL,
AND THEY KNEW EXACTLY
WHERE TO FIND THE DISCS.
FUTURE MAN:
THEY WEREN'T ACTING ALONE.
SILIK: MY SHIPS ARE FAST.
WE CAN OVERTAKE THEM
AND DESTROY "ENTERPRISE."
FUTURE MAN: HAVE YOUR SHIPS
BRING ME ARCHER.
ALLOW "ENTERPRISE" TO CONTINUE.
BUT WE NEED TO RECOVER
THE DISCS.
FUTURE MAN: ARCHER.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
THE LAST TIME YOU FAILED ME.
IT WAS 10 MONTHS AGO.
HE BROUGHT ME BACK 10 MONTHS.
BUT I KNEW EVERYTHING
I KNOW NOW.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
T'POL: AS I'VE TOLD YOU,
THE VULCAN SCIENCE DIRECTORATE
HAS CONCLUDED
THAT TIME TRAVEL IS IMPOSSIBLE.
ARCHER: WELL, GOOD FOR
THE VULCAN SCIENCE DIRECTORATE.
MAYBE THEY CAN TELL ME
HOW I WOKE UP YESTERDAY
KNOWING EXACTLY
WHERE THAT SULIBAN SHIP WAS.
OR HOW I SUDDENLY
HAD THE ABILITY
TO CONSTRUCT A QUANTUM BEACON
TO SEE THROUGH ITS CLOAK.
AND WHILE THEY'RE AT IT,
THEY MIGHT AS WELL TELL ME
HOW I KNEW
WHERE TO FIND THOSE DISCS.
T'POL: ALL VALID QUESTIONS.
BUT TO CONCLUDE
THAT THE ONLY ANSWER IS
THAT YOU ACQUIRED THIS
INFORMATION FROM A DEAD CREWMAN
WHO TRANSPORTED YOU BACK
THROUGH TIME IS ILLOGICAL.
ARCHER: WHY DON'T YOU GIVE ME
ANOTHER EXPLANATION?
T'POL: I CAN'T.
ARCHER: BECAUSE THERE ISN'T ONE.
I GOT A CALL FROM TRIP.
SOMETHING ABOUT INSPECTION PODS.
IT WAS THE EXACT SAME CALL I GOT
THE DAY BEFORE
THEY FOUND KLAANG.
WORD FOR WORD.
T'POL: PERHAPS
YOU WERE DREAMING.
ARCHER: LISTEN...
I NEVER THOUGHT
THIS WAS POSSIBLE, EITHER.
BUT...
I TRAVELED THROUGH TIME.
AND I NEED YOU TO BELIEVE ME.
T'POL: WHY?
ARCHER: BECAUSE IT'S HARD ENOUGH
TRYING TO FATHOM ALL THIS
WITHOUT HAVING
MY SCIENCE OFFICER--
A COLLEAGUE
WHO I TRUST AND RELY ON,
THE PERSON WHO GOT ME TO
STOP FEELING SORRY FOR MYSELF--
ACCUSING ME OF BEING
AN HALLUCINATING MADMAN.
T'POL: I DON'T REMEMBER
ACCUSING YOU OF ANYTHING.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
REED: BRIDGE TO ARCHER.
ARCHER: YES?
REED: WE'RE GETTING SOME
STRANGE READINGS, SIR.
IT MIGHT NOT BE A BAD IDEA
FOR YOU TO COME OUT HERE.
REED: I'VE TAKEN THE LIBERTY
OF ASKING COMMANDER TUCKER
TO JOIN US.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
REED: WE'RE HAVING TROUBLE
BALANCING THE WARP FIELD.
ARCHER: LOOKS OK TO ME.
REED: IT'S ODD.
IT'LL BE STABLE ONE MOMENT,
AND THEN FOR NO REASON,
IT'LL GO SLIGHTLY
OUT OF ALIGNMENT.
TUCKER: WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
DOING TO MY ENGINES?
THE AUTO-STABILIZERS
AREN'T FUNCTIONING PROPERLY.
THE COMPUTER RAN
ITS LAST DIAGNOSTIC ON THEM
LESS THAN 10 MINUTES AGO.
TUCKER: THEY LOOK FINE.
REED: WELL, THEY'RE NOT.
WE'VE HAD TO REALIGN
THE FIELD A DOZEN TIMES
OVER THE LAST HOUR.
LOAD TORPEDOES.
AND STANDBY ALL WEAPONS.
DEPLOY THE BEACONS, TRAVIS.
MODIFY THE VIEWSCREEN
AND AIM THE BEACONS AFT.
ARCHER: SWING THEM DOWN SLOWLY.
TUCKER: IT LOOKS LIKE WE'RE
IN A SWARM OF CLOAKED BEES.
CHARGE THE PHASE CANNONS.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI: WE'RE BEING HAILED.
ARCHER: PUT IT THROUGH.
I WOULDN'T ADVISE
USING YOUR WEAPONS, JONATHAN.
PERHAPS IF WE DECLOAK,
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND WHY.
MALCOLM?
THEY'RE ALL ARMED
WITH HIGH-YIELD
PARTICLE WEAPONS, SIR.
HOW MANY COULD YOU TAKE OUT?
BEFORE THEY OPEN FIRE?
NOT ENOUGH, SIR.
ONE OF MY SHIPS IS APPROACHING
YOUR STARBOARD DOCKING PORT.
I'D LIKE YOU
TO BOARD IT IMMEDIATELY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT WITH ME?
YOU HAVE 5 MINUTES.
IF YOU DON'T COMPLY,
I HAVE PERMISSION
TO DESTROY ENTERPRISE.
HOW DO I KNOW YOU WON'T
DESTROY "ENTERPRISE" EITHER WAY?
YOU HAVE MY WORD, CAPTAIN.
AND YOU ALSO HAVE
4 1/2 MINUTES LEFT.
I'M PLACING YOU IN COMMAND.
I ADVISE YOU TO MAINTAIN
YOUR PRESENT COURSE AND SPEED.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
BUT TRY TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND...
ESPECIALLY WHEN IT COMES
TO THINGS
THE VULCAN SCIENCE
DIRECTORATE SAYS ARE IMPOSSIBLE.
I'LL TRY.
CAPTAIN, THIS IS CRAZY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE GONNA DO?
ARCHER: T'POL'S
IN COMMAND NOW, TRIP.
DO WHATEVER YOU CAN TO HELP HER.
THAT GOES FOR ALL OF YOU.
KEEP AN EYE ON PORTHOS
FOR ME, WOULD YOU?
REMEMBER...
NO CHEESE.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
YOUR CAPTAIN'S PLAYING A VERY
DANGEROUS GAME, SUBCOMMANDER.
GAME?
HE HAS 30 SECONDS LEFT.
DID HE THINK I WASN'T SERIOUS?
THE TURBOLIFT'S ON "E" DECK.
IT'S EMPTY.
T'POL: WHERE IS HE?
I'M NOT READING HIS BIO-SIGNS.
HE MUST BE ON THE SULIBAN SHIP.
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER IS
NO LONGER ABOARD "ENTERPRISE."
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD CHECK WITH
THE VESSEL YOU SENT FOR HIM.
I THOUGHT HE WAS SMARTER
THAN THIS.
HE COULD HAVE SAVED
ALL YOUR LIVES.
WHAT A WASTE.
THE DOCKED SHIP IS MOVING AWAY.
IT'S TARGETING OUR WARP CORE.
THEY'RE ALL TARGETING
THE WARP CORE.
DANIELS: 10 MINUTES AGO,
THAT VISTA WAS MORE BEAUTIFUL
THAN ANYTHING YOU COULD IMAGINE.
ARCHER: WHERE AM I?
I-I HAD BREAKFAST IN THAT ROOM
LESS THAN HALF AN HOUR AGO.
THEN I WAS INSTRUCTED
TO BRING YOU HERE.
THEY TOLD ME THAT THE TIMELINE
WOULDN'T BE SAFE
IF YOU BOARDED
THAT SULIBAN SHIP.
SOMEONE WAS VERY MISTAKEN.
ARCHER: WHERE IS HERE?
YOU'RE IN THE 31st CENTURY,
CAPTAIN.
OR WHAT'S LEFT OF IT.
YOU SAID THE SULIBAN
WOULDN'T FOLLOW US,
THAT WE'D MAKE IT SAFELY
TO THE VULCAN SHIP.
DANIELS: AS FAR AS I WAS TOLD,
THAT WAS EXACTLY WHAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO OCCUR.
ARCHER: SO YOU'RE TELLING ME
THIS JUST HAPPENED?
IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
IT JUST HAPPENED.
NO.
IT LOOKS LIKE IT HAPPENED
A LONG TIME AGO.
ARCHER: IF BRINGING ME HERE
CAUSED THIS, THEN SEND ME BACK.
I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES WITH SILIK.
DANIELS: Y-YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ALL OUR EQUIPMENT--
THE TIME PORTALS--
HAVE BEEN DESTROYED.
EVERYTHING'S BEEN DESTROYED.
THERE'S NO WAY TO SEND YOU BACK.