[EXPLOSIONS]
ARCHER: LAST TIME
ON "ENTERPRISE"...
HOSHI: THERE'S NOTHING LEFT.
NO BUILDINGS, NO TREES,
NO PEOPLE.
ARCHER: THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE WERE 3,600 COLONISTS.
THE MISSION'S BEEN CANCELED.
TUCKER: I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE
LETTING THEM DO THIS TO US.
YOU'VE WAITED ALL YOUR LIFE
TO COMMAND THIS SHIP.
DANIELS: HISTORY NEVER
RECORDED THE DISASTER.
SOMEONE
VIOLATED THE TEMPORAL ACCORD,
SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T
WANT YOUR MISSION TO SUCCEED.
ARE YOU TELLING ME
THAT "ENTERPRISE"
DIDN'T CAUSE THAT EXPLOSION?
HE BROUGHT ME BACK 10 MONTHS.
BUT I KNEW EVERYTHING
I KNOW NOW.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
THE SULIBAN DESTROYED
THAT COLONY.
WE'RE GOING BACK TO GET PROOF.
FUTURE MAN: HAVE YOUR
SHIPS BRING ME ARCHER.
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER
IS NO LONGER ABOARD ENTERPRISE.
I THOUGHT HE WAS SMARTER
THAN THIS.
HE COULD HAVE SAVED
ALL YOUR LIVES.
IT'S TARGETING OUR WARP CORE.
DANIELS: YOU'RE IN THE 31st
CENTURY, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: IF BRINGING ME HERE
CAUSED THIS, THEN SEND ME BACK.
I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES WITH SILIK.
DANIELS: Y-YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE TIME PORTALS--
THEY'VE BEEN DESTROYED.
EVERYTHING'S BEEN DESTROYED.
THERE'S NO WAY
TO SEND YOU BACK.
ARCHER: AND NOW THE CONCLUSION.
HE'S NOT ONBOARD.
YOU MUST HAVE SENSORS
THAT CAN CONFIRM THAT.
YOU'VE LIED TO ME BEFORE.
IF YOU DON'T TELL ME
WHERE HE IS,
I'LL HAVE NO ALTERNATIVE
BUT TO--
COME SEE FOR YOURSELF
OR SEND YOUR SOLDIERS.
YOU'LL REALIZE
I'M TELLING THE TRUTH.
DROP OUT OF WARP
AND PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
REED: SECURITY TEAMS TO
DOCKING PORTS 1, 2, AND 3.
T'POL:
THIS IS SUBCOMMANDER T'POL.
ALL SECURITY TEAMS REMAIN
WHERE YOU ARE.
TUCKER: ARE YOU CRAZY?
HOW DO WE KNOW HOW MANY SULIBAN
ARE COMING ABOARD?
THEY COULD TRY
TO TAKE OVER THE SHIP.
THERE ARE 30 ARMED VESSELS
SURROUNDING US.
UNLESS I'M MISTAKEN,
THEIR WEAPONS ARE STILL
TARGETING OUR WARP CORE.
MR. REED?
SO UNLESS YOU HAVE
A BETTER SUGGESTION...
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: IF THIS PLACE
WAS DESTROYED
AS LONG AGO
AS IT SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN,
THEN WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YOU AND YOUR WATCHDOG BUDDIES
DON'T EXACTLY
FIT IN WITH ALL THIS.
DANIELS: YOU'RE THINKING
OF TIME TRAVEL
LIKE WE'RE IN SOME
H.G. WELLS NOVEL.
WE'RE NOT.
IT'S FAR MORE COMPLICATED.
THERE'S NO WAY FOR YOU
TO UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: TRY ME.
LISTEN, I REALIZE
YOUR LITTLE UTOPIA IS GONE,
AND I SYMPATHIZE,
BUT IF YOU'RE TELLING ME
THE TRUTH,
IF YOU'VE BROUGHT ME 800 YEARS
INTO THE FUTURE--
INTO THIS FUTURE--
I THINK I DESERVE SOME ANSWERS.
DANIELS: I DON'T
HAVE ANY ANSWERS.
AND YOU'RE RIGHT.
I SHOULDN'T BE HERE,
WHICH MEANS YOU SHOULDN'T
BE HERE, EITHER,
BUT YOU ARE.
WE ARE.
[LAUGHS]
WE BROUGHT YOU HERE
TO PROTECT THE TIMELINE.
[LAUGHS]
WE DID QUITE A JOB.
ARCHER: WHAT'S WRONG?
DANIELS: IT'S GONE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S GONE?
DANIELS: THE MONUMENT.
IT WAS RIGHT HERE,
ON THE SAME STREET
AS THE LIBRARY.
IT WAS OBVIOUSLY
NEVER BUILT.
ARCHER: WHY IS THAT A PROBLEM?
WHO DID IT COMMEMORATE?
DANIELS: NOT WHO.
ARCHER: THEN WHAT?
DANIELS: AN ORGANIZATION.
A FEDERATION.
IT DOESN'T EXIST FOR YOU,
NOT--NOT YET.
ARCHER: BUT IT WILL?
FINE.
KEEP YOUR MISSING
MONUMENT TO YOURSELF.
WHERE'S THIS LIBRARY
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT?
DANIELS: UH, IT SHOULD
BE RIGHT DOWN THERE,
IF IT WAS EVER BUILT.
AND EVEN IF IT WAS,
IT WILL BE OF NO HELP.
ALL THE DATA IS STORED
ELECTRONICALLY.
DANIELS: BOOKS
MADE WITH PAPER.
THERE AREN'T SUPPOSED
TO BE BOOKS HERE.
ARCHER: WELL, THERE ARE.
SO I SUGGEST
WE USE SOME OF THEM
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT YOU DID
TO THE LAST THOUSAND YEARS
WHEN YOU BROUGHT ME HERE
THIS MORNING.
THEY HAVEN'T
BEEN DUPLICATED.
SILIK: IS HE CORRECT?
T'POL: DON'T YOU BELIEVE
YOUR SCANNERS?
SILIK: IS HE CORRECT?
HOSHI: WE DIDN'T HAVE
TIME TO MAKE A COPY.
TUCKER: LEAVE HER ALONE!
SILIK: LOWER YOUR WEAPON.
IF WE FIND CAPTAIN ARCHER
ABOARD THIS VESSEL,
YOU'LL ALL BE...
PUNISHED FOR LYING TO ME.
ALIEN: HE'S NOT HERE
UNLESS HE'S DEAD.
BUT WE DID FIND THIS.
SILIK: WHERE?
ALIEN: IN THAT LIFT.
IT'S AN HOUR OLD, MAYBE TWO.
SILIK: WHEN I SAW HIM LAST,
YOUR CAPTAIN SPOKE
OF A TEMPORAL COLD WAR.
WHAT WAS HE TALKING ABOUT?
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER BELIEVED
CREWMAN DANIELS WAS
FROM THE FUTURE.
BUT IF I RECALL,
YOU KILLED HIM.
SILIK: WHAT ELSE?
T'POL: NOTHING ELSE.
SILIK: THERE'S A TEMPORAL
SIGNATURE IN YOUR TURBOLIFT.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW OF THAT?
T'POL: THE LAST TIME
WE SAW CAPTAIN ARCHER,
HE WAS ENTERING THAT TURBOLIFT.
SILIK: PERHAPS YOU HAVEN'T
BEEN LYING TO ME.
YOU, SHUT DOWN ALL COM SYSTEMS
AND COMPUTER TERMINALS
WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF ENGINEERING AND THE BRIDGE.
CONFINE ALL OF THEM
TO THEIR QUARTERS.
SILIK: IF ANYONE RESISTS--
ALIEN: UNDERSTOOD.
TUCKER: HEY!
T'POL: UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
IT WOULD BE BEST
TO DO WHAT HE SAYS, COMMANDER.
THEY'RE 3 DAYS OVERDUE.
FORREST: I TOLD YOU, AMBASSADOR,
ARCHER SAID
HE WAS RETURNING WITH PROOF
THAT THEY WEREN'T RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE TRAGEDY ON PARAAGAN II.
YOU ALSO TOLD ME
STARFLEET HAD ORDERED HIM
TO DELIVER SUBCOMMANDER T'POL
AND HIS MEDICAL OFFICER
TO THE VULCAN SHIP "D'KYR."
THEY'RE 3 DAYS OVERDUE.
WILLIAMS: THE "D'KYR" HAS
LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
HAVE THEY DETECTED "ENTERPRISE"?
SOVAL: CAPTAIN ARCHER'S
NEGLIGENCE CAUSED THE DEATH
OF 3,000 COLONISTS.
YOUR SUPERIORS INSTRUCTED THEM
TO RETURN TO EARTH.
THEIR MISSION IS OVER.
THEY HAVEN'T FOLLOWED
THOSE INSTRUCTIONS.
FORREST: YOU DIDN'T ANSWER
THE COMMANDER'S QUESTION.
HAS YOUR SHIP
DETECTED "ENTERPRISE"?
SOVAL: THE "D'KYR" SAID
THEY WERE JOINED
BY A NUMBER OF OTHER VESSELS.
THEY'RE NO LONGER
WITHIN SENSOR RANGE.
MAN: WHAT KIND OF VESSELS?
SOVAL: THEY WERE AT TOO
GREAT A DISTANCE TO IDENTIFY.
"ENTERPRISE" HAS
IGNORED OUR HAILS
AND DEFIED STARFLEET'S ORDERS.
I HAVE NO CHOICE BUT TO SEND
THE "D'KYR" IN PURSUIT.
FORREST: JONATHAN ARCHER
DOESN'T REPORT TO YOU.
SOVAL: NO, HE DOESN'T.
BUT SUBCOMMANDER T'POL DOES.
AND SINCE SHE WOULD NEVER COMPLY
WITH HIS PRESENT ACTIONS,
I HAVE TO CONCLUDE THAT SHE'S
BEING HELD AGAINST HER WILL.
MAN: I KNOW YOU DON'T THINK MUCH
OF ARCHER, AMBASSADOR,
BUT HE IS NOT IN THE HABIT
OF KIDNAPPING VULCANS.
FORREST: FINE.
YOU SEND YOUR SHIP.
WHATEVER ARCHER'S UP TO, I'M
SURE HE'S GOT A GOOD REASON.
HE KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING.
SOVAL: DOES HE REALLY?
ALIEN: HAVE YOU CYCLED THROUGH
THE SUB-TEMPORAL HARMONICS?
SILIK: HE'S NEVER FAILED
TO RESPOND BEFORE.
ALIEN: PERHAPS HE'S ANGRY THAT
WE DIDN'T RETURN WITH ARCHER.
SILIK: ARCHER WASN'T
ON "ENTERPRISE."
WHY ISN'T HE RESPONDING?
I NEED INSTRUCTIONS.
ALIEN: HE SAID TO
DESTROY "ENTERPRISE"
IF WE COULDN'T
BRING HIM ARCHER.
WE SHOULD TOW THEM OUT
OF THE NEBULA AND DO IT NOW.
SILIK: THAT TEMPORAL SIGNATURE,
IT CHANGES EVERYTHING.
IF ARCHER WAS PULLED
THROUGH TIME,
WE NEED NEW INSTRUCTIONS.
WHERE IS HE?
ALIEN: IF HE'S ANGRY WITH YOU,
YOU'LL BE PUNISHED AGAIN.
WE SHOULD DESTROY "ENTERPRISE."
SILIK: HAVE
THE SURGEONS PREPARE.
THEN BRING ME THE VULCAN.
ARCHER: I HAVEN'T FOUND
A SINGLE REFERENCE
TO THIS FEDERATION
YOU TALKED ABOUT.
DANIELS: I DOUBT YOU WILL.
ARCHER: BECAUSE THAT MONUMENT
WASN'T THERE?
DANIELS: BECAUSE
YOU WEREN'T THERE.
ARCHER: SO I DISAPPEAR ONE DAY
AND ALL HISTORY CHANGES?
DANIELS: I'VE LOOKED THROUGH
THE 21st AND 22nd CENTURIES.
EVERYTHING LOOKS RIGHT,
UP UNTIL THE WARP 5 PROGRAM.
AFTER THAT, NOTHING LOOKS RIGHT.
ARCHER: THERE WERE
A LOT OF PEOPLE INVOLVED
IN THE WARP 5 PROGRAM.
DANIELS: WE DIDN'T BRING A LOT
OF PEOPLE HERE THIS MORNING.
WE JUST BROUGHT YOU.
ARCHER: THE ROMULAN STAR EMPIRE.
WHAT'S THAT?
DANIELS: MAYBE YOU SHOULDN'T
BE READING THAT.
ARCHER: I DON'T GET IT.
WHAT COULD I HAVE DONE
THAT COULD HAVE BEEN
SO IMPORTANT?
DANIELS: IT WASN'T JUST YOU.
IT WAS EVENTS YOU
HELPED SET IN MOTION.
ARCHER: THIS TIMELINE--
THE ONE YOU SAY
NO LONGER EXISTS--
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME
ABOUT IT
IF MY MISSION HAD CONTINUED?
DANIELS: IT WOULD HAVE
LED TO OTHERS.
ARCHER: AND?
OK.
WHAT ABOUT
THIS FEDERATION?
WAS EARTH PART OF IT?
WAS I PART OF IT?
DANIELS: SILIK WANTED YOU,
NOT THE DATA DISKS.
THE PEOPLE HE ANSWERED TO
WERE MORE INTERESTED
IN CAPTURING JONATHAN ARCHER
THAN IN BLAMING "ENTERPRISE"
FOR THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE COLONY.
THEY OBVIOUSLY KNEW
WHAT ROLE YOU WERE GOING TO PLAY
IN THE MONTHS OR--
OR YEARS TO COME.
BY TAKING YOU AWAY
FROM THE 22nd CENTURY,
I CAUSED EXACTLY
WHAT I WAS TRYING TO PREVENT.
ARCHER: YOU'VE LOST ME.
DANIELS: THE ONLY CHANCE I HAVE
OF RESTORING MY CENTURY
IS BY GETTING YOU
BACK TO YOURS.
ARCHER: SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE GOT
A CHICKEN OR THE EGG PROBLEM.
YOU SAID
YOUR TIME PORTALS ARE GONE,
ALL YOUR TECHNOLOGY.
THERE ISN'T EVEN
ELECTRICITY HERE.
YOU GONNA FIND A BICYCLE,
TURN IT INTO A TIME MACHINE?
DANIELS: MAYBE WE DON'T NEED
A TIME MACHINE.
DO YOU HAVE YOUR COMMUNICATOR?
ARCHER: AND MY SCANNER.
DANIELS: MAY I?
THE PEOPLE THE SULIBAN
WERE WORKING FOR
CAME FROM ABOUT 300 YEARS AGO.
THEY COULDN'T TRAVEL
THROUGH TIME,
BUT THEY DID DEVELOP A WAY
TO SEND BACK IMAGES
OF THEMSELVES--
TO COMMUNICATE THROUGH TIME.
ARCHER: YOU CAN'T DO THAT
WITH THOSE.
DANIELS: NO. IT'S A LITTLE BIT
MORE COMPLICATED BUT NOT MUCH.
WE LEARNED HOW TO DO IT
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
BUT WE'RE GOING TO NEED
A FEW THINGS
THAT MIGHT NOT BE
TOO EASY TO FIND.
WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
WHERE IS ARCHER?
I DON'T KNOW.
SILIK: WHO ARE YOU WORKING WITH
FROM THE FUTURE?
T'POL: THE VULCAN SCIENCE
DIRECTORATE HAS DETERMINED
THAT TIME TRAVEL
IS IMPOSSIBLE.
SILIK: DOES CAPTAIN ARCHER
AGREE WITH THAT OPINION?
T'POL: IT'S NOT AN OPINION.
SILIK: DOES ARCHER AGREE
WITH THAT DETERMINATION?
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER BELIEVES
CREWMAN DANIELS COMES
FROM THE FUTURE.
SILIK: BUT DANIELS IS DEAD.
CAPTAIN ARCHER CLAIMS
HE SAW DANIELS TWO DAYS AGO.
SILIK: YOUR CAPTAIN IS GONE.
DID DANIELS TAKE HIM INTO
THE PAST OR THE FUTURE?
T'POL: THE VULCAN SCIENCE
DIRECTORATE HAS DETERMINED
THAT TIME TRAVEL IS IMPOSSIBLE.
[SILIK SIGHS]
ARCHER: I CAN'T BE SURE,
BUT I THINK THAT'S COPPER.
DANIELS: WELL DONE.
I NEED YOU TO UNWRAP IT
AND POUND IT INTO SMALL STRIPS
NO MORE THAN A MILLIMETER THICK.
[STATIC]
HELLO?
PLEASE REPEAT.
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND.
[STATIC]
I STILL CAN'T UNDERSTAND YOU.
TRY MODULATING
THE SUB-CARRIER WAVE.
TUCKER: MALCOLM, IT'S...
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
BARELY.
YOU'RE GOING TO NEED
TO BOOST THE SIGNAL.
TUCKER: ANY BETTER?
YEAH.
REED: I THOUGHT
THE COM WAS OFFLINE.
IT IS.
I'M ROUTING THE SIGNAL
THROUGH THE E.P.S. GRID.
I CAN TALK TO ANY DOORBELL
ON "B" DECK.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
SAME AS YOU, I GUESS.
TUCKER: LOCKED IN TIGHT.
REED: AND THE OTHERS?
TUCKER: I CAN'T GET IN CONTACT
WITH T'POL FOR SOME REASON,
AND HOSHI AND TRAVIS
ARE ON "C" DECK.
REED: ANY THOUGHTS
ABOUT HOW WE'RE GONNA GET
RID OF THESE SULIBAN?
TUCKER: ONE STEP AT A TIME.
THE FIRST THING I NEED TO DO
IS FIGURE OUT
HOW TO TAP INTO THE DOOR COMS
ON "C" DECK.
I'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
SIT TIGHT.
I WASN'T PLANNING
ON GOING ANYWHERE.
ARCHER: ANY LUCK?
DANIELS: I STILL HAVE
THE SPATIAL COORDINATES
OF "ENTERPRISE,"
BUT WITHOUT
A QUANTUM DISCRIMINATOR,
IT'S GOING TO BE VERY TRICKY
TO CONTACT THE SHIP
ON THE SAME DAY YOU LEFT.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT YOU BUILT
THESE THINGS IN HIGH SCHOOL.
DANIELS: YEAH, WHERE
QUANTUM DISCRIMINATORS
WERE IN EVERY DESK.
ARCHER: WHY IS THE SAME DAY
SO IMPORTANT?
WHAT WOULD BE WRONG
WITH MAKING CONTACT
A WEEK BEFORE I LEFT
OR EVEN A MONTH BEFORE?
DANIELS: I MADE
THE BIGGEST MISTAKE
IN THE HISTORY OF TIME TRAVEL
THIS MORNING.
I DON'T INTEND
TO MAKE IT ANY WORSE.
[SHIVERING]
[STATIC]
ARCHER: THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
T'POL, THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
I DON'T THINK IT'S WORKING.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS.
ARCHER: YOU DON'T
KNOW WHERE WHO IS?
SUBCOMMANDER,
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
I'M HAVING TROUBLE
UNDERSTANDING YOU.
CAPTAIN ARCHER'S GONE.
A TEMPORAL READING
IN THE TURBOLIFT.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS.
ARCHER: DANIELS BROUGHT ME
TO THE FUTURE.
THAT'S WHAT THE TEMPORAL
READING WAS ALL ABOUT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
SCIENCE VULCAN DIRECTORATE
HAS DETERMINED
THAT TIME TRAVEL IS...
NOT FAIR.
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
JUST TELL ME,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WE'RE ALL CONFINED
TO OUR QUARTERS.
ARCHER: WHERE ARE YOU?
I TOLD YOU. IN MY QUARTERS.
NO, I MEAN ENTERPRISE.
WHERE'S ENTERPRISE?
THERE'S A HELIX OUT MY WINDOW.
T'POL, LISTEN TO ME.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO FIND A WAY
TO GET TO DANIELS' QUARTERS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YOU'RE ON THE CEILING.
WHY AREN'T YOU ON A MONITOR?
THERE'S NO TECHNOLOGY
WHERE I AM.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU WERE IN THE FUTURE.
T'POL, DO YOU REMEMBER WHEN I
ASKED YOU TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND?
YES.
THERE'S A LOT MORE
AT STAKE HERE
THAN BRINGING ME BACK
OR THE MISSION.
I NEED YOU TO LISTEN TO ME
VERY CAREFULLY.
I NEED YOU TO TRUST ME.
IT WON'T WORK.
WE CAN ONLY ACCESS
THE DECOUPLING PINS
FROM OUTSIDE OUR QUARTERS.
SO IF WE CAN'T PICK THE LOCKS,
WHAT ABOUT THE SHAFTS
THAT HOUSE THE E.P.S. CONDUITS?
TRAVIS: THEY'RE ADJACENT
TO THE AIR DUCTS.
THEY WERE PRETTY MUCH BLOCKED
OFF WHEN THE SHIP WAS COMPLETED.
IT WOULD BE
TOO TIGHT A SQUEEZE.
WHAT'S YOUR DEFINITION
OF TOO TIGHT?
WELL, YOU OR I COULDN'T
GET THROUGH THEM.
REED: MAYBE A CHILD, OR--
TUCKER: OR HOSHI?
REED: IT'S POSSIBLE,
BUT IT WOULD BE DIFFICULT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, HOSHI?
TUCKER: YOU WILLING
TO GIVE IT A TRY?
ISN'T THERE SOME OTHER WAY
THAT I CAN HELP OUT?
SOMETHING THAT NEEDS
TRANSLATING?
YOU KNOW HOW CLAUSTROPHOBIC
I AM.
THERE'S NO ONE ELSE THAT CAN GET
THROUGH THOSE CRAWLSPACES
UNLESS WE COULD REACH
CREWMAN NAIMAN.
TRAVIS: SHE'S PRETTY SMALL.
T'POL: THERE'S NO TIME.
IF THIS IS GOING TO WORK,
WE NEED TO BEGIN NOW.
ENSIGN SATO?
HOSHI:
HOW FAR WOULD I HAVE TO GO
TO GET TO THE DOCTOR'S QUARTERS?
T'POL: 40 METERS, MAYBE 45.
THEN HOW FAR
TO LIEUTENANT REED'S?
TUCKER: IT'S NOT
THAT FAR, HOSHI.
YOU CAN DO IT.
WE NEED YOU TO DO IT.
[KNOCK KNOCK]
HOSHI?
GOOD GUESS.
PHLOX: HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
GREAT.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'D JUST LIKE TO
GET THIS OVER WITH.
GOOD LUCK.
AAH!
WHATEVER YOU'RE ABOUT TO SAY,
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT.
JUST GET ME A SHIRT.
T'POL: THIRD DIMENSION.
TIMELINE, TIMELINE.
FIRST. SECOND.
SECOND AND--
THAT DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE.
ALIEN: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
FIRST AND THIRD DIMENSION.
STAND UP, VULCAN.
UP!
T'POL: NO.
NO! NO!
NO!
NO! STOP!
T'POL: YOU CERTAINLY
TOOK YOUR TIME.
HE HAD THIS PRESSED
AGAINST MY HEAD.
TUCKER: HAD TO BE SURE
THEY WERE PREOCCUPIED.
YOU POSITIVE
YOU'RE WILLING TO DO THIS?
IT COULD GET PRETTY UGLY.
REED: I'M POSITIVE.
TUCKER: YOU'VE GOT 30 MINUTES.
REED: GOOD LUCK.
T'POL: IF THEY
REGAIN CONSCIOUSNESS,
DON'T HESITATE
TO USE THESE.
HOSHI: DON'T WORRY.
TUCKER: LET'S GO.
[DOOR OPENS]
[COUGHS]
SILIK: DID YOU THINK
WE WOULDN'T BE
WATCHING DANIELS' QUARTERS?
REED: I GUESS I WASN'T THINKING.
SILIK: I GUESS YOU WEREN'T.
BUT YOU SHOULD BE
THINKING NOW--
THINKING ABOUT WHAT
WILL HAPPEN TO YOU
IF YOU DON'T ANSWER
MY QUESTIONS.
ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT THAT,
LIEUTENANT REED?
GOOD.
NOW TELL ME WHAT THIS IS.
WHAT DOES IT DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
[COUGHING]
SILIK: WHAT DOES IT DO?
REED: I DON'T KNOW.
PLEASE!
SILIK: YES?
I WAS TOLD TO DESTROY IT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT DOES.
WHO TOLD YOU TO DESTROY IT?
[REED CHOKING]
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
BEFORE HE LEFT.
HE DIDN'T WANT YOU TO FIND IT.
SILIK: AND WHY WOULD THAT BE?
REED: HE THOUGHT YOU WOULD
USE IT TO CONTACT SOMEONE.
I DON'T KNOW WHO.
I SWEAR IT!
[COUGHS]
SILIK: HAVE THE LIEUTENANT
RETURNED TO HIS QUARTERS.
READY!
[ALARM]
ENGINEERING,
HOW DID THIS HAPPEN?
ENGINEERING!
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
WHAT IS IT?
ALIEN: THE ANTIMATTER STREAM
HAS BEEN COMPROMISED.
SHUT DOWN THE WARP REACTOR.
ALIEN: OUR ENGINEERS
AREN'T RESPONDING.
I'VE SENT SOLDIERS.
KEEP ME INFORMED.
[ALARM]
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
YES?
ALIEN: THESE HUMANS ARE
GREATER FOOLS THAN I THOUGHT.
THEY'D RATHER COMMIT MASS
SUICIDE THAN SUBMIT TO US.
SILIK:
DID YOU CORRECT THE PROBLEM?
IT'S TOO LATE.
THE REACTOR'S GOING TO BREACH.
WE CAN'T ENDANGER THE HELIX.
EVACUATE YOUR SOLDIERS
AND HAVE "ENTERPRISE"
TOWED OUT OF THE NEBULA.
THERE'S VERY LITTLE TIME. WILL
YOU ALERT THE TRACTOR TEAMS?
YOU DO IT. I'M BUSY.
IS THAT YOU? CAN YOU HEAR ME?
REPORT, ENSIGN.
TRAVIS: THE ANTIMATTER STREAM
IS BACK TO NORMAL.
T'POL: YOU MAY HAVE OVERDONE
YOUR PYROTECHNIC DISPLAY.
THE SCORCHING ON THE STARBOARD
NACELLE IS EXTENSIVE.
TUCKER: WELL, I'LL
TRY TO REMEMBER THAT
NEXT TIME WE HAVE
TO FAKE A REACTOR BREACH.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI:
CELL SHIPS. 30 OF THEM.
35. APPROACHING AT HIGH WARP.
T'POL: MAINTAIN YOUR COURSE
AND SPEED, ENSIGN.
I'VE TRIED TO REACH YOU.
I'VE TRIED FOR TWO DAYS.
I DID WHAT YOU TOLD ME, BUT
ARCHER WASN'T ON "ENTERPRISE."
THERE WAS SOME KIND
OF TEMPORAL SIGNATURE.
I NEED INSTRUCTIONS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO OPERATE THIS DEVICE.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
FIGURE: YOU'RE AN UGLY...
I HEAR YOU,
BUT I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
REPEAT WHAT YOU SAID, PLEASE.
REPEAT WHAT YOU SAID.
I SAID, YOU'RE AN UGLY BASTARD.
ARCHER: YOU TRY
SHAPE-SHIFTING ON ME
OR PULLING ONE OF
YOUR CHAMELEON ROUTINES,
AND I PROMISE YOU, SILIK,
I'LL BLOW YOUR HEAD OFF.
ARCHER: HAS "ENTERPRISE"
LEFT THE NEBULA?
SILIK: CAN YOU SEE?
I'VE BROUGHT YOU ARCHER!
HE'S HERE! ARCHER'S HERE!
THERE'S NO NEED TO PUNISH ME.
ARCHER: WHERE'S MY SHIP, SILIK?
SILIK: THEY'VE LEFT.
THEY'RE GONE.
ARCHER: HOW MANY CELL SHIPS
DID YOU SEND AFTER THEM?
SILIK!
SILIK: I DON'T KNOW. 20, 30.
ARCHER: WELL, YOU'RE
GONNA CALL THEM OFF.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA GIVE ME
THOSE DATA DISKS BACK.
NOW GET UP.
SILIK: MY SOLDIERS
WON'T LET YOU LEAVE.
ARCHER: SHUT UP!
GET GOING!
HOSHI, ANY SIGN
OF THE VULCAN SHIP?
NOT YET.
TRAVIS: HULL PLATING ON
THE PORT-AFT QUARTER'S DOWN.
ALTER COURSE
10 DEGREES STARBOARD.
[ALARM]
THEY'RE CLOSING.
THE LEAD SHIPS
ARE OVERTAKING US.
TRAVIS:
PORT HULL PLATING'S DOWN.
VENTRAL PLATING AS WELL.
HOSHI: WHY'D THEY STOP FIRING?
TRAVIS: WHY WASTE AMMUNITION?
THEY HAVE US SURROUNDED.
ARE LONG-RANGE SENSORS
STILL OPERATIONAL?
NO VULCAN SHIP.
SUBCOMMANDER?
T'POL: I SEE THEM.
TUCKER: SON OF A BITCH.
HE DID IT.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
ONE CELL SHIP APPROACHING AFT.
STAND DOWN WEAPONS.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
"ENTERPRISE" TO SULIBAN VESSEL.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD, "ENTERPRISE."
GOOD TO HEAR YOUR VOICE,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD TO HEAR YOURS, TOO.
I FEEL LIKE I'VE BEEN AWAY
FOR A THOUSAND YEARS.
IS EVERYONE ALL RIGHT?
T'POL: LIEUTENANT REED
SUFFERED SOME MINOR INJURIES,
BUT HE'S RECOVERING
IN SICK BAY.
CAPTAIN, I'M CURIOUS.
WHY DIDN'T THE OTHER CELL SHIPS
TRY TO STOP YOU?
ARCHER: I KNOW IT'S NOT
STANDARD STARFLEET PROCEDURE,
BUT I TOOK A HOSTAGE.
BY THE TIME HE WAKES UP,
WE'LL BE LONG GONE.
ARCHER: REQUEST
PERMISSION TO DOCK.
PERMISSION GRANTED.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE JOINED
THE VULCAN SHIP "D'KYR."
IT SEEMS THAT STARFLEET
AND THE HIGH COMMAND
ARE EAGER TO DISCUSS
THE FUTURE OF OUR MISSION.
SOVAL: WHILE YOUR EXPLANATION
OF HOW YOU OBTAINED THESE DISKS
IS SOMEWHAT IMPLAUSIBLE,
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT ENTERPRISE
WAS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE DESTRUCTION OF THE COLONY.
IT MAY SEE SOMEWHAT
IMPLAUSIBLE TO YOU, BUT--
PLEASE ALLOW ME
TO FINISH, CAPTAIN.
IN LESS
THAN A SINGLE EARTH YEAR,
YOU'VE ENGAGED
IN ARMED CONFLICTS
WITH OVER A DOZEN SPECIES.
YOU'VE ESCALATED THE CONFLICT
BETWEEN MY PEOPLE
AND THE ANDORIANS,
WHICH INCLUDED THE DESTRUCTION
OF ONE OF OUR MOST
SACRED MONASTERIES.
YOU HELPED 89 SULIBAN
ESCAPE FROM DETENTION.
YOU MAY CLAIM TO BE ON
A MISSION OF EXPLORATION.
I, HOWEVER, CONSIDER YOU
RECKLESS AND IRRESPONSIBLE,
A DANGER TO THE QUADRANT.
REGARDLESS OF THE EVIDENCE
PRESENTED HERE,
I PLAN TO ADVISE
THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
NOT TO CHANGE ITS RECOMMENDATION
TO STARFLEET.
"ENTERPRISE" SHOULD BE RECALLED.
TUCKER: YOU GUYS HAVE
WANTED TO SCRUB THIS MISSION
FROM DAY ONE!
WE PROVED TO YOU THAT WE DIDN'T
KILL THOSE 3,600 PEOPLE,
BUT YOU DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT!
YOU'RE PATHETIC!
FORREST:
THAT'S ENOUGH, COMMANDER.
FORREST: NO ONE'S
MORE PLEASED THAN I AM
THAT "ENTERPRISE" WASN'T
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE TRAGEDY.
BUT AMBASSADOR SOVAL'S
ARGUMENT MAY BE VALID.
STARFLEET COMMAND HAS
A DIFFICULT DECISION
TO MAKE HERE.
WHEN I WAS IN MY EARLY 20s,
ON A TRIP TO EAST AFRICA,
I SAW A GAZELLE GIVING BIRTH.
IT WAS TRULY AMAZING.
WITHIN MINUTES, THE BABY
WAS STANDING UP--
STANDING UP ON ITS OWN.
A FEW MORE MINUTES,
AND IT WAS WALKING,
AND BEFORE I KNEW IT,
IT WAS RUNNING ALONGSIDE
ITS MOTHER,
MOVING AWAY WITH THE HERD.
HUMANS AREN'T LIKE THAT,
AMBASSADOR.
WE MAY COME FROM THE SAME PLANET
AS THOSE GAZELLES,
BUT WE'RE PRETTY MUCH
HELPLESS WHEN WE'RE BORN.
IT TAKES US MONTHS
BEFORE WE'RE ABLE TO CRAWL,
ALMOST A FULL YEAR
BEFORE WE CAN WALK.
OUR DEEP-SPACE MISSION
ISN'T MUCH DIFFERENT.
WE'RE GOING TO STUMBLE,
MAKE MISTAKES--
I'M SURE MORE THAN A FEW
BEFORE WE FIND OUR FOOTING.
BUT WE'RE GOING TO LEARN
FROM THOSE MISTAKES.
THAT'S WHAT BEING HUMAN
IS ALL ABOUT.
I'M SORRY YOU CAN'T SEE THAT.
SOVAL: YOUR ANALOGY IS
VERY COLORFUL, CAPTAIN,
BUT I QUESTION
WHETHER IT ADDRESSES
THE CONSEQUENCES
OF YOUR ACTIONS.
T'POL: THE CONCEPT OF LEARNING
FROM ONE'S MISTAKES
SHOULDN'T BE DIFFICULT
FOR A VULCAN OF YOUR WISDOM
TO UNDERSTAND, AMBASSADOR.
OUR ANCESTORS
DISCOVERED HOW TO SUPPRESS
THEIR VOLATILE EMOTIONS
ONLY AFTER CENTURIES
OF SAVAGE CONFLICT.
T'POL: YOU SPOKE OF THE
DESTRUCTION OF THE MONASTERY.
WHAT ABOUT THE VULCAN
LISTENING POST
THAT CAPTAIN ARCHER
FOUND THERE?
I WOULD HOPE THAT OUR PEOPLE
HAVE LEARNED FROM THOSE EVENTS
THAT USING A SACRED SANCTUARY
TO SPY ON OTHERS
WAS A DISHONORABLE PRACTICE,
TO SAY THE LEAST.
I DON'T WISH TO CONTRADICT
CAPTAIN ARCHER,
BUT LEARNING FROM ONE'S MISTAKES
IS HARDLY EXCLUSIVE TO HUMANS.
THEIR MISSION SHOULD BE
ALLOWED TO CONTINUE.
THE COMMAND COUNCIL
WILL REVIEW THE EVIDENCE
AND LISTEN TO WHAT'S
BEEN SAID HERE TODAY.
I'M SURE THEY'LL HEAR
FROM THE VULCANS AS WELL.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW AS SOON
AS THERE'S A DECISION.
GOOD LUCK, JONATHAN...
ALL OF YOU.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
ARCHER: I CAN'T BE CERTAIN,
BUT CREWMAN FULLER MIGHT
HAVE SEEN ME COMING IN HERE.
SHE TENDS TO BE DISCREET.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
I THINK YOU PUT IT OVER THE TOP.
FORREST SAID NONE OF
THE OTHERS COULD BELIEVE IT
WHEN YOU WENT TO BAT FOR US,
NOT TO MENTION THAT LITTLE
LISTENING-POST LECTURE
YOU GAVE TO SOVAL.
T'POL: YOU SPOKE TO THE ADMIRAL?
ARCHER: HE WOKE ME UP
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
I ASSUME WITH GOOD NEWS.
I THINK YOU PUT IT OVER THE TOP.
T'POL: I STILL DON'T
BELIEVE IN TIME TRAVEL.
ARCHER: THE HELL YOU DON'T.