ARCHER: SAY WHEN.
T'POL: WHEN.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU DRANK WINE.
T'POL: UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I'LL ALLOW MYSELF
A SMALL INDULGENCE.
TRIP: MAKE MINE
A LARGE INDULGENCE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
ARCHER:
TO OUR SCIENCE OFFICER.
IT'S BEEN ONE YEAR
TO THE DAY
SINCE YOU OFFICIALLY
JOINED OUR CREW.
TRIP: HERE'S TO MANY MORE.
T'POL: I APPRECIATE
THE SENTIMENT,
BUT I'M SIMPLY CARRYING OUT
MY ASSIGNMENT.
ARCHER: THAT'S NO SMALL
ACCOMPLISHMENT,
CONSIDERING THE PREVIOUS RECORD
FOR A VULCAN SERVING ON
A HUMAN SHIP WAS TWO WEEKS.
T'POL: 10 DAYS.
I'VE BEEN FILLING OUT
YOUR ANNUAL CREW EVALUATION --
JUST A FORMALITY.
I UNDERSTAND.
THE HIGH COMMAND HAS REQUESTED
MY EVALUATION OF YOU.
JUST A FORMALITY.
THERE'S SOMETHING IN YOUR RECORD
I'VE BEEN MEANING
TO ASK YOU ABOUT.
WHILE YOU WERE STATIONED
IN SAUSALITO,
YOU TOOK A FIVE-DAY LEAVE.
YES?
YOU WENT TO AN OLD MINING TOWN
IN PENNSYLVANIA -- CARBON CREEK?
SEEMS LIKE AN ODD PLACE
TO TAKE A VACATION.
VULCANS DON'T TAKE VACATIONS.
ARCHER: THEN, IF I MAY ASK,
WHY'D YOU GO THERE?
T'POL: IS THIS PART
OF MY EVALUATION?
ARCHER: JUST CURIOUS.
T'POL: IT WAS A PERSONAL MATTER.
TRIP: YOU HAD A PERSONAL MATTER
IN CARBON CREEK, PENNSYLVANIA?
TRIP, IF SHE DOESN'T
WANT TO TELL US --
SEEMS A LITTLE UNFAIR.
WE TELL HER PLENTY OF STORIES.
T'POL: YOU'D LIKE ME
TO TELL YOU A STORY?
IF IT'S A GOOD ONE.
I WENT TO CARBON CREEK BECAUSE
I WANTED TO VISIT THE SITE
OF FIRST CONTACT
BETWEEN HUMANS AND VULCANS.
ARCHER: THEN YOU WERE ABOUT
3,000 KILOMETERS OFF.
THAT TOOK PLACE IN MONTANA.
ACTUALLY, IT DIDN'T.
TRIP: EVERY SCHOOLKID KNOWS
THAT ZEFRAM COCHRANE
MET THE VULCANS IN BOZEMAN,
MONTANA, ON APRIL 5, 2063.
I'VE BEEN THERE.
THERE'S A STATUE.
T'POL: IN FACT, THE VULCANS
VISITED EARTH LONG BEFORE THEN.
MY SECOND FOREMOTHER
WAS ONE OF THEM.
YOUR WHO?
MY MOTHER'S MOTHER'S MOTHER.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO HEAR THE STORY?
MAN: ♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
I CAN'T COMPENSATE.
THE RE-FUSION PRESSURE
IS STILL DROPPING.
IF OUR ORBIT DECAYS ANY FURTHER,
WE'LL BE DETECTED.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY HAD GONE TO EARTH
TO INVESTIGATE THE LAUNCH
OF ITS FIRST ARTIFICIAL
SATELLITE CALLED SPUTNIK.
DURING THEIR THIRD WEEK
OF GATHERING INFORMATION
ABOUT HUMANITY,
THEIR IMPULSE MANIFOLD
BEGAN TO MALFUNCTION.
THEY HAD NO CHOICE BUT
TO ATTEMPT AN EMERGENCY LANDING.
TRY TO FIND AN ISOLATED AREA.
SEND A DISTRESS CALL
TO THE HIGH COMMAND.
WOMAN: 100 KILOMETERS.
DEPLOY THE STABILIZERS.
OUR LANDING VECTOR IS TOO STEEP.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
[ SPARKING, SIZZLING ]
[ COUGHING ]
MAN: ARE YOU HURT?
WOMAN: I DON'T THINK SO.
CAPTAIN.
MAN: WHAT ARE YOUR ORDERS?
ARCHER: WHY DID THE VULCANS
KEEP THIS A SECRET?
T'POL: THE INCIDENT
IS WELL-DOCUMENTED
AT THE SCIENCE DIRECTORATE
AND THE SPACE COUNCIL.
TRIP: ON VULCAN?
T'POL: OF COURSE.
TRIP: HANG ON.
T'MIR WAS
YOUR GREAT-GRANDMOTHER?
I'D BE THE LAST PERSON
TO QUESTION YOUR MATH,
BUT AREN'T YOU MISSING
A FEW GENERATIONS?
SPUTNIK WAS 200 YEARS AGO.
DON'T FORGET
HOW LONG VULCANS LIVE.
RIGHT.
JUST HOW OLD ARE YOU?
IT'S GOT TO BE IN HER RECORD.
TRIP, THAT'S
CLASSIFIED INFORMATION.
ARCHER: PLEASE. GO ON.
THEIR SUBSPACE TRANSCEIVER
WAS DAMAGED IN THE CRASH.
THEY HAD NO WAY OF KNOWING
IF THEIR DISTRESS SIGNAL
HAD EVEN BEEN TRANSMITTED.
THEY'D USED UP THEIR EMERGENCY
RATIONS WITHIN A WEEK.
AFTER FIVE DAYS WITHOUT FOOD,
THEIR SITUATION
WAS GROWING DESPERATE.
[ BEEPING ]
TWO LIFE-FORMS.
FASCINATING.
ONE OF THOSE CREATURES
COULD SUSTAIN US FOR SOME TIME.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING WE EAT IT?
IT'S LOGICAL TO TAKE
EXTREME MEASURES TO SURVIVE.
EVEN RESORTING TO SAVAGERY?
THAT MAY NOT BE NECESSARY.
OUR SCANS SHOWED A SETTLEMENT
APPROXIMATELY
SIX KILOMETERS AWAY.
IF WE ARE EXPOSED,
WE COULD CONTAMINATE
THEIR CULTURE.
AND WHEN THEY FIND OUR BODIES
AFTER WE STARVE,
WILL THAT CONTAMINATE
THEIR CULTURE?
BETTER TO LEAVE THEM
WITH A MYSTERY
THAN WITH THREE LIVING ALIENS.
WE SHOULD AT LEAST INVESTIGATE
THE POSSIBILITIES.
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
I'M WILLING TO TAKE THE RISK.
MESTRAL.
REMAIN HERE.
HOW DO YOU SUGGEST
WE PROCEED?
WE'LL NEED TO DISGUISE
OURSELVES.
WE'RE HERE TO FIND FOOD,
NOTHING ELSE.
WE'LL KEEP CONTACT WITH THE
HUMANS TO AN ABSOLUTE MINIMUM.
IF WE MUST INTERACT
WITH THEM, I WILL SPEAK.
WHAT IS IT?
I BELIEVE YOU HAVE
THAT GARMENT ON...BACKWARDS.
PRISONERS?
THEY DON'T APPEAR
TO BE RESTRAINED.
MORE LIKELY LABORERS.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
THESE PEOPLE WERE CAPABLE
OF LAUNCHING
AN ARTIFICIAL SATELLITE.
RADIO ANNOUNCER:
AND HE GETS THE SIGN.
AND HERE'S THE PITCH.
[BAT HITS BALL ]
DIXON HITS A SCORCHER
DOWN THE RIGHT-FIELD LINE.
THE FIRST BASEMAN MAKES
A STAB AT IT, BUT NO.
ELLIS IS CHARGING HARD
FROM RIGHT FIELD.
HE SCOOPS IT UP AND FIRES.
IT'S GONNA BE CLOSE.
THERE'S A COLLISION
AT THE PLATE,
BUT WILCOX HANGS ON TO
THE BALL, AND THOMPSON IS OUT!
[ GROANING ]
OH, MY, WHAT A PLAY.
AND THAT'S TWO OUT.
SOME TYPE OF COMBAT,
NO DOUBT.
I BELIEVE IT MAY BE
AN ENTERTAINMENT.
[ COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING ]
MAN: ♪ GENTLY FALLS
THIS LONELY... ♪
A COMMUNAL GATHERING PLACE.
DO THEY HAVE FOOD?
IT APPEARS SO.
REMEMBER.
I WON'T SPEAK.
MAN: ♪ I KNOW THE REASON
YOU MUST BE AWAY ♪
♪ BUT, OH,
HOW MY TEAR GENTLY FALLS ♪
♪ GENTLY FALLS
THE FLOWING SNOW ♪
THIS BITTER TEAR ♪
♪ THE SANDS OF WAR
ARE KEEPING YOU FROM ME ♪
MAN: ♪ FOR ANOTHER YEAR ♪
WOMAN: ANOTHER?
MAN: NAH, I'LL SETTLE UP.
WOMAN: ALL RIGHT.
MAN: I'M NEXT.
MAN: ♪ OH, HOW MY TEAR
GENTLY FALLS ♪
CURRENCY.
YES. THE PAPER APPEARS
TO HAVE VALUE.
MAN: ♪ OH, HOW MY TEAR
GENTLY FALLS ♪
THANKS, BILLY.
WOMAN: WHAT CAN I GET YOU?
DO YOU HAVE ANYTHING
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE CURRENCY?
YOU MEAN FREE?
MAN: ♪ BUT, OH,
HOW MY TEAR GENTLY FALLS ♪
MAN: WHAT BRINGS YOU
TO CARBON CREEK?
MAN: ♪ I KNOW THE REASON ♪
T'MIR: WE HAD AN ACCIDENT WITH
OUR VEHICLE OUTSIDE YOUR TOWN.
WOMAN: ARE YOU OKAY?
T'MIR: WE'RE FINE.
MAN: ♪ OH, HOW MY TEAR
GENTLY FALLS ♪
YOU FOLKS MARRIED?
NO.
WE'RE...BUSINESS ASSOCIATES.
THERE'S A GAS STATION
UP THE ROAD.
I'D BE HAPPY TO GIVE YOU A LIFT.
NO, THANK YOU.
SUIT YOURSELF.
ANYBODY UP FOR A GAME?
QUARTER A BALL?
BOY: I'LL PLAY.
MAN: YOU BETTER ASK YOUR MOTHER,
JACKIE.
COME ON, MOM,
WE COULD USE THE MONEY.
GO ON UPSTAIRS
AND DO YOUR HOMEWORK.
WOMAN: I'LL BRING YOU UP
SOME DINNER.
MESTRAL: I'M UP FOR A GAME.
T'MIR: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I TOLD YOU
NOT TO SPEAK TO ANYONE.
MESTRAL:
I CAN DEFEAT HIM.
T'MIR: YOU DON'T EVEN
KNOW THE RULES.
MESTRAL: IT'S SIMPLE.
I THOUGHT YOU DIDN'T HAVE
ANY MONEY.
HE DOESN'T.
WELL, SORRY, PAL.
THERE'S NOTHING IN IT FOR ME.
IT'S TIME FOR US TO GO.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO WORK SOMETHING OUT.
IF YOU WIN, I'LL PAY UP.
IF I WIN, YOUR BUSINESS
ASSOCIATE HAS A DRINK WITH ME.
WE ACCEPT YOUR TERMS.
WE DO NOT.
THE GAME IS BASED
ON SIMPLE GEOMETRY.
IT WOULDN'T CHALLENGE
A VULCAN CHILD.
T'MIR: NO.
MESTRAL: WE NEED THEIR CURRENCY.
WHAT IF YOU LOSE?
I'LL HAVE TO...
SOCIALIZE WITH HIM.
WOULD YOU RATHER DIE
OF STARVATION?
TOUGH BREAK.
THE NUMBER-8 BALL...
IN THAT POCKET.
[ BELL JINGLING ]
MAN: IT'S AN EXCELLENT PRODUCT,
AND IF YOU THINK ABOUT IT,
FINANCIALLY...
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
MESTRAL: CRYOGENICS.
DO YOU SUPPOSE
THEY'VE EXPERIMENTED
WITH PROTEIN REPLICATORS?
T'MIR: WHY DIDN'T YOU ASK
THE MERCHANT?
YOU SEEMED WILLING
TO ENGAGE EVERYONE ELSE
IN CONVERSATION.
I THINK THAT WINE'S
GONE TO YOUR HEAD.
WHAT ARE YOU IMPLYING?
TWO VULCANS STROLL INTO A BAR,
HUSTLE A FEW GAMES OF POOL,
AND WALK OUT
WITH AN ARMLOAD OF TV DINNERS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE AN OLD EPISODE
OF "THE TWILIGHT ZONE."
[ LAUGHTER ]
IF YOU'RE NOT INTERESTED
IN HEARING THE REST --
ARCHER: HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
WE DIDN'T SAY
WE WEREN'T INTERESTED.
THEY REALIZED
THEY COULDN'T RELY ON GAMBLING,
SO THEY TOOK WHATEVER
EMPLOYMENT THEY COULD FIND
WHILE THEY WAITED FOR
A RESCUE VESSEL TO ARRIVE.
[ GRUNTING ]
T'POL: BUT AS THE WEEKS PASSED,
IT SEEMED LESS LIKELY
THAT THEIR DISTRESS CALL
HAD BEEN RECEIVED,
AND IT BECAME MORE DIFFICULT
FOR THEM TO AVOID THE HUMANS.
TV ANNOUNCER:
THE TEST OF A NUCLEAR DEVICE
IS DESIGNED FOR TACTICAL USE
IN PLACE OF ARTILLERY.
ZERO HOUR WAS JUST AFTER...
WOMAN: NOTHING LIKE AN ATOMIC
TEST TO MAKE YOUR DAY.
MESTRAL:
DOESN'T IT CONCERN YOU?
THE BOMB?
IT SCARES THE HELL OUT OF ME.
I'D HATE TO SEE HUMANITY
DESTROY ITSELF.
WOMAN: THAT MAKES TWO OF US.
BOY: WANT TO SHOOT SOME 8-BALL?
WOMAN: JACK.
I'VE GOT A GEOMETRY MIDTERM
NEXT WEEK. IT'S GOOD PRACTICE.
NICE TRY, BUT THERE'S BETTER
WAYS TO PREPARE FOR A MATH TEST.
ARE YOU INTERESTED
IN MATHEMATICS?
JACK: OH, IT'S WHAT I WANT
TO STUDY AT COLLEGE.
MECHANICAL ENGINEERING.
IF I GET TO GO.
YOU WILL.
HE GOT A SCHOLARSHIP.
ONLY A PARTIAL ONE.
IT'S STILL A SCHOLARSHIP,
AND YOU WORKED HARD FOR IT.
EVERYBODY'S BEEN PITCHING IN
TO HELP PAY FOR HIS EXPENSES --
BOOKS, ROOM AND BOARD.
WOMAN: YOU CAN SHOOT ONE RACK,
AND THAT'S IT.
YOUR BREAK.
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS,
GUNSHOTS ]
[ SIGHS ]
MAN: THIS IS THE
THIRD TIME THIS WEEK
I'VE HAD TO FIX
MRS. GARRETT'S SINK.
MESTRAL: PERHAPS SHE ENJOYS
YOUR COMPANY.
IT MIGHT BE TOLERABLE
IF HER SON DIDN'T INSIST
ON CALLING ME MOE.
WHY DOES HE DO THAT?
THERE IS A COMIC ACTOR KNOWN
AS A STOOGE WITH THAT NAME.
THE BOY BELIEVES
WE HAVE SIMILAR HAIR.
THERE IS A RESEMBLANCE.
THIS IS INTOLERABLE.
I'M A WARP FIELD ENGINEER.
THEN PERHAPS YOU CAN HELP ME
CONSTRUCT
A SUBSPACE TRANSCEIVER.
I TOLD YOU, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IF WE REMAIN HERE, WE'LL DIE.
T'MIR: THIS WORLD'S ON THE BRINK
OF SELF-ANNIHILATION.
MESTRAL: I DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
BECAUSE YOUR FASCINATION WITH
THIS SPECIES IS BLINDING YOU.
YOU SIT FOR HOURS EACH DAY
IN FRONT OF THIS IDIOTIC DEVICE.
I'M DOING RESEARCH.
PERHAPS IF YOU SPENT MORE TIME
OBSERVING HUMAN BEHAVIOR,
YOU MIGHT NOT HAVE SUCH
A PESSIMISTIC VIEW OF THEM.
T'MIR: OPEN YOUR EYES.
THEY REVEL IN VIOLENCE.
THEY DEVOTE WHAT LITTLE
TECHNOLOGY THEY HAVE
TO DEVISING WAYS
OF KILLING EACH OTHER.
SO DID WE CENTURIES AGO.
THEY JUST HAVEN'T REALIZED
THEIR POTENTIAL YET.
WHAT POTENTIAL?
THEY HAVE GREAT EMPATHY
AND COMPASSION.
LOOK HOW WE'VE BEEN MADE
TO FEEL WELCOME.
[ TURNS OFF TELEVISION ]
ONLY BECAUSE
THEY BELIEVE WE'RE HUMAN.
IF THEY DISCOVERED THE TRUTH,
DO YOU THINK THEY'D BE
SO COMPASSIONATE?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO THE SHIP.
WHY?
THIS ANTENNA IS INADEQUATE.
I BELIEVE I CAN USE
A WAVEFORM DISCRIMINATOR
TO ENHANCE IT.
IT'LL BE SAFER
TO GO AFTER DARK.
YOU CAN'T RISK
BEING FOLLOWED.
I NEED TO GO NOW.
"I LOVE LUCY" IS ON TONIGHT.
MAN: HOWDY.
MESTRAL: HELLO.
[ BRAKES SQUEAL ]
HI. YOU'RE RIGHT ON TIME.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
MESTRAL: IT WAS DIFFERENT THAN
SEEING IT ON TELEVISION,
MORE...INVIGORATING.
WOMAN: WELL, THERE'S
ANOTHER GAME NEXT WEEK
IF YOU'D LIKE TO GO.
OR WE COULD DO
SOMETHING ELSE.
TAKE IN A MOVIE?
THAT WOULD BE ENJOYABLE.
CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
YES.
WHAT ARE YOU HIDING
UNDER THAT CAP,
A POINTED HEAD?
YOU'RE NOT FROM MARS, ARE YOU?
OH, I-I-I DIDN'T MEAN
TO MAKE FUN OF YOU.
I'M NOT OFFENDED.
MAY I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
PLEASE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR...MATE?
YOU MEAN MY HUSBAND?
YES.
HE LEFT A LONG TIME AGO.
JACK USED TO GET LETTERS
FROM HIM EVERY NOW AND THEN.
THE LAST WE HEARD,
HE'D MOVED TO PHOENIX.
I WAS HOPING HE WOULD
HELP WITH JACK'S COLLEGE,
BUT I GUESS
WE'RE ON OUR OWN.
I CAN UNDERSTAND
WHY HE WOULDN'T WANT
TO HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH ME, BUT...
I'M SORRY.
I'M USUALLY BETTER AT KEEPING
A LID ON MY EMOTIONS.
IT'S -- IT'S NOT ALWAYS EASY.
I KNOW.
WELL, UM...
I'M DUE BACK AT THE PINE TREE.
WILL I SEE YOU LATER?
OH, I-I-I DIDN'T MEAN TO.
I THOUGHT -- I THOUGHT --
OH, GOD.
PLEASE, I WAS SIMPLY SURPRISED.
IT WAS...VERY PLEASANT.
PLEASANT?
WASN'T THAT
AN APPROPRIATE RESPONSE?
WELL, IT'S BEEN A WHILE
SINCE I KISSED A MAN,
BUT, STILL, I WAS HOPING
IT'D BE A LITTLE BIT
MORE THAN PLEASANT.
I DID SAY VERY PLEASANT.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
WE'VE GOT COMPANY.
[ SIGHS ] I SHOULD GO.
THANK YOU AGAIN.
WAVEFORM DISCRIMINATOR?
I WENT TO A BASEBALL GAME
IN DOYLESTOWN.
MORE RESEARCH?
MAGGIE INVITED ME.
I DIDN'T THINK IT
WOULD BE A PROBLEM.
THEN WHY DID YOU LIE
ABOUT IT?
BECAUSE I KNEW YOU
WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU WERE ENGAGING
IN INTIMATE ACTIVITY.
I DIDN'T INITIATE IT.
YOU'RE TO HAVE NO FURTHER
CONTACT WITH THAT WOMAN.
YOU CAN'T MAKE THAT DECISION.
I'M STILL IN COMMAND.
COMMAND OF WHAT?
OUR MISSION IS OVER.
IT'S TIME TO ACCEPT THE FACT
THAT WE MAY NEVER
LEAVE THIS WORLD.
I WAS JUST GONNA PLAY SOME POOL.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO BOTHER YOU.
UM, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I WAS ABOUT TO MEDITATE.
REALLY?
ARE YOU JUST TRYING
TO CLEAR YOUR MIND
OR...REACH A HIGHER
SPIRITUAL PLANE?
I SPEND A LOT OF TIME
AT THE LIBRARY.
STUDYING MEDITATION TECHNIQUES?
UH, DIFFERENT THINGS.
UH, MOSTLY ABOUT PLACES
I'D LIKE TO VISIT.
UH, LIKE TIBET.
THE -- THE BUDDHIST MONKS THERE
MEDITATE EVERY DAY.
AND IN INDIA, THEY'VE GOT
THESE MYSTICS CALLED FAKIRS.
SUPPOSEDLY THEY CAN ALMOST
STOP THEIR HEARTS
JUST BY USING WILLPOWER.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED
WHAT A DISCIPLINED MIND
CAN ACCOMPLISH.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU STUDY
AT THIS LIBRARY?
ASTRONOMY, UM, LITERATURE.
SOMETIMES I'LL JUST PICK A BOOK
OFF THE SHELF AND START READING.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WHAT DO YOU LIKE TO READ?
I HAVE AN INTEREST IN ASTRONOMY,
AS WELL.
OH, REALLY?
DID YOU KNOW THAT, UH,
MINUTES AFTER DUSK,
WHEN THE SUN IS JUST RIGHT,
YOU CAN SEE SPUTNIK
WITH THE NAKED EYE.
MAYBE TOMORROW I COULD SHOW YOU.
I'VE SEEN IT ALREADY.
IT'S AMAZING.
DON'T YOU THINK?
WELL, I'LL LET YOU GET BACK
TO YOUR MEDITATING.
IT WAS NICE TALKING TO YOU.
AND YOU.
MAN: MESTRAL!
MESTRAL: HELLO.
HEY! I GOT TICKETS TO
THE BALL GAME THIS WEEKEND.
IT'S A DOUBLE-HEADER.
TIM'S GOING, GAVIN, JACK.
MAGGIE.
I'M AFRAID I CAN'T.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU LATELY?
MAGGIE SAYS YOU HAVEN'T EVEN --
[ EXPLOSION ]
UGH!
MESTRAL:
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, BILLY?
BILLY: YEAH.
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING,
ALARM BLARES ]
T'MIR: WHY DO YOU
NEED US HERE?
MESTRAL: I'M LOOKING
FOR A PARTICLE WEAPON.
THE ARMORY CASE --
HELP ME FIND IT.
MAN: WHY?
MESTRAL: THERE'S BEEN
AN ACCIDENT IN THE MINE.
AT LEAST 20 MEN ARE TRAPPED.
IT COULD TAKE THE HUMANS DAYS
TO FREE THEM.
T'MIR: WE CAN'T INTERFERE.
MESTRAL: THEY'LL DIE.
YOU'D LET THEM SUFFOCATE...
EVEN IF WE COULD PREVENT IT.
MAN: WHAT IF THEY
SEE THE WEAPON?
WE'LL BE CERTAIN THEY DON'T.
AT BEST, THESE HUMANS
ONLY LIVE TO BE 60 OR 70.
IS IT WORTH THE RISK
JUST TO EXTEND THEIR LIVES
A FEW MORE YEARS?
MAN: WE CAN'T CONTAMINATE
THEIR CULTURE.
THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH CONTAMINATION.
IT HAS TO DO WITH COMPASSION.
COMPASSION...IS AN EMOTION.
THEY'RE MY FRIENDS,
AND I'M GOING TO HELP THEM.
DON'T TRY TO STOP ME.
[ JACKHAMMERS POUNDING,
INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
[ ALARM BLARES ]
[ BEEPING ]
YES.
T'MIR: PROCEED 22 METERS,
THEN TURN RIGHT AT THE JUNCTION.
Mestral: Understood.
T'Mir: In eight meters,
you'll find a narrow opening
near the ground that leads
to an abandoned shaft.
MAN: I THINK WE NEED MORE
GUYS DOWN THERE, THOUGH.
MAN: IS THE RIDE
FREE UP THERE?
MAN: YEAH.
[ COUGHING ]
T'Mir: There's a stratum
of quartz on the wall
opposite the opening.
MESTRAL: I SEE IT.
SET YOUR DISPERSAL RADIUS
TO SEVEN DEGREES.
TWO MORE METERS.
HOW FAR?
APPROXIMATELY 30 METERS.
MAN: HERE, OVER HERE.
[ COUGHING ]
T'POL: AFTER RESCUING
THE 12 MINERS,
MESTRAL BECAME
SOMETHING OF A HERO THAT DAY.
ARCHER: DIDN'T PEOPLE WONDER
HOW HE GOT THEM OUT?
T'POL: I'M SURE THEY DID,
BUT NO ONE EVER DISCOVERED
THE TRUTH.
THREE MONTHS PASSED,
AND JUST AS THEY HAD
RESIGNED THEMSELVES TO THE FACT
THAT, IN ALL LIKELIHOOD,
THEY WOULD NEVER LEAVE EARTH...
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPING ]
T'MIR.
Man: This is Captain Tellus
of the Vulcan
survey vessel D'Vahl.
I am responding
to your distress signal.
T'MIR: WE THOUGHT
IT WASN'T TRANSMITTED.
Tellus: Your signal was received
by a Tellarite freighter.
It took them some time to
forward it to the High Command.
We're approaching
the system now.
Meet us at the crash site
in three days.
UNDERSTOOD.
I HEAR YOU'RE LEAVING?
THAT'S CORRECT.
WHERE TO?
HOME.
UP NORTH.
I'M GONNA MISS YOU.
YOU'RE ABOUT THE MOST
INTERESTING PEOPLE
I'VE MET IN THIS TOWN.
I'M SURE YOU'LL MEET A LOT OF
INTERESTING PEOPLE AT COLLEGE.
I'M NOT GOING.
WHAT? WHY NOT?
WE COULDN'T COME UP
WITH THE REST OF THE MONEY.
THE DEADLINE
FOR THE TUITION'S FRIDAY, SO...
WHAT WILL YOU DO?
KEEP SAVING, I GUESS.
FIND A JOB.
JACK: MOM DOESN'T WANT ME
ANYWHERE NEAR THE MINE,
BUT THAT'S WHERE THE WORK IS
AROUND HERE.
CAN YOU TRY AGAIN NEXT YEAR
FOR THE SCHOLARSHIP?
I'LL REAPPLY,
BUT THERE'S NO GUARANTEE.
I'M SURE THEY WILL
OFFER IT TO YOU AGAIN.
AND IF NOT,
THERE'S ALWAYS THE LIBRARY.
STILL A LOT OF BOOKS
I HAVEN'T READ.
GOOD LUCK UP NORTH.
CARBON CREEK'S NOT EXACTLY
A VACATION SPOT,
BUT I HOPE
YOU'LL COME VISIT US.
PERHAPS.
HE TOOK THOSE COLLEGE BOARDS.
GOT THE HIGHEST SCORE
OF ANYBODY IN THE COUNTY.
IT'S NOT FAIR.
[ DOOR SHUTS ]
SO...YOU'RE THE LADY
WITH THE INVENTION THAT'S
GOING TO CHANGE THE WORLD.
[ RIPPING ]
MORNING.
JACK?!
[ CHUCKLES ]
T'MIR: DIDN'T YOU TERMINATE
YOUR EMPLOYMENT?
MAN: YES.
BUT I PROMISED MRS. GARRETT I'D
REPAIR THIS SUCTION DEVICE.
MESTRAL: IT'S UNFORTUNATE THAT
YOU'LL BE LEAVING THESE PEOPLE
WITHOUT EXPERIENCING
ONE THING THEY HAVE TO OFFER.
SUCH AS...ALCOHOL...
FROZEN FISH STICKS...
THE CONSTANT THREAT
OF NUCLEAR ANNIHILATION?
THERE'S MUCH MORE TO THEM.
YOU JUST REFUSE TO SEE IT.
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH.
I HAVEN'T.
I PLAN TO STAY HERE.
IF THIS IS
YOUR ATTEMPT AT HUMOR --
THEY'RE ON THE VERGE
OF COUNTLESS SOCIAL
AND TECHNOLOGICAL ADVANCEMENTS.
I HAVE THE UNIQUE OPPORTUNITY
TO STUDY AN EMERGING SPECIES.
MAN: THAT'S WHAT YOU'VE DONE,
MUCH CLOSER THAN WE ANTICIPATED.
YOUR DUTY IS TO RETURN TO VULCAN
AND REPORT YOUR FINDINGS.
THERE'S STILL MORE TO LEARN
ABOUT THESE PEOPLE.
ALL OF THEM OR JUST ONE?
[ SIGHS ]
THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH MAGGIE.
SHE HAS HELPED ME APPRECIATE
THEIR CULTURE,
BUT I DON'T INTEND TO REMAIN
IN CARBON CREEK.
WHERE WOULD YOU GO?
TO ONE OF THEIR LARGER CITIES
AT FIRST.
AFTER THAT, I'M NOT CERTAIN.
THERE'S SO MUCH TO SEE.
THE HIGH COMMAND
WILL NEVER ALLOW IT.
TELL HIM IT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
T'MIR?
T'MIR: PERHAPS I CAN
ARRANGE FOR YOU TO BE
ON THE NEXT SURVEY SHIP.
IN ANOTHER 20 YEARS,
RUNNING MORE STATISTICAL SCANS
FROM HIGH ORBIT?
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
TELLUS: WHERE IS YOUR CAPTAIN?
HE WAS KILLED IN THE CRASH.
TELLUS: THERE WERE FOUR VULCANS
ABOARD YOUR VESSEL.
MESTRAL DIED
IN THE CRASH AS WELL.
WE CREMATED THEIR REMAINS.
TRIP: DO YOU REALIZE YOU'VE JUST
REWRITTEN OUR HISTORY BOOKS?
T'POL: A FOOTNOTE, AT BEST.
TRIP: FOOTNOTE?
THIS IS LIKE FINDING OUT
NEIL ARMSTRONG
WASN'T THE FIRST MAN
TO WALK ON THE MOON.
PERHAPS HE WASN'T.
OH.
HOW LONG DID THIS MESTRAL
STAY ON EARTH?
THE REST OF HIS LIFE,
PRESUMABLY.
AND THAT WOULD BE, WHAT,
ANOTHER 100, 150 YEARS?
POSSIBLY LONGER.
[ SCOFFS ]
AN ALIEN IS LEFT
ON EARTH IN THE 1950s,
LIVES THROUGH, WHAT,
30 PRESIDENTS,
TRAVELS THE WORLD,
AND NO ONE NOTICES HIM?
AND WHAT HAPPENED WHEN HE
FINALLY KICKED THE BUCKET?
DID THE UNDERTAKER JUST SHRUG
AND IGNORE HIS EARS?
T'POL: YOU ASKED ME
TO TELL YOU A STORY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
IT WAS A GOOD ONE.
BUT DID IT REALLY HAPPEN?
AS I SAID, YOU ASKED ME
TO TELL YOU A STORY.
DAMN, CAPTAIN.
SHE PUT ONE OVER ON US.
YOU DID GO TO CARBON CREEK.
IF YOU CHECK MY RECORD,
YOU'LL NOTE
THAT I ALSO VISITED
YELLOWSTONE PARK
AND THE CARLSBAD CAVERNS.
I'M A SCIENTIST.
THAT INCLUDES GEOLOGY.
THANK YOU FOR THE MEAL.
ARCHER: UH. MY PLEASURE.
YOU'VE CERTAINLY
KEPT US ENTERTAINED.
GOOD NIGHT.
[ SIGHS ]