[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
Come in.
ARCHER: GOOD MORNING.
CAPTAIN.
SLEEP WELL?
WELL ENOUGH.
I WASN'T SURE WHAT
YOU WANTED FOR BREAKFAST,
SO I TOOK THE LIBERTY
OF HAVING CHEF PREPARE
HIS FAMOUS EGGS BENEDICT.
OH. THAT'LL BE FINE, SIR.
ARCHER: AH.
YOU PLAN TO EAT STANDING UP?
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ SIGHS ]
THIS ISN'T A VISIT TO THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE, MALCOLM.
AT EASE.
OH, THANK YOU, SIR.
I JUST WASN'T SURE
WHETHER YOU CALLED ME HERE
TO DISCUSS SOMETHING.
NO. NO BUSINESS.
I JUST WANTED TO HAVE
A LONG-OVERDUE MEAL
WITH MY ARMORY OFFICER.
AH.
I HEARD THAT ENGLAND MADE IT
TO THE FINALS
IN THE WORLD CUP.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
THE WORLD CUP?
SOCCER?
OH.
I'M AFRAID I DON'T
MUCH FOLLOW FOOTBALL, SIR.
ANY...SPORTS YOU DO FOLLOW?
NO. NOT PARTICULARLY.
THANKS.
YOU'RE WELCOME, SIR.
[ SIGHS ]
I'VE BEEN WORKING ON
THE DUTY ROSTER, SIR.
WE ONLY HAVE
TWO CREWMEN ASSIGNED
TO THE ARMORY FULL-TIME.
IF WE ADDED A THIRD,
ENSIGN TANNER WOULD BE FREE
TO BEGIN THOSE UPGRADES
TO THOSE TORPEDO LAUNCHERS
I TOLD YOU ABOUT.
DIDN'T YOUR MOTHER
EVER TELL YOU
NOT TO BRING
YOUR HOMEWORK TO THE TABLE?
SIR?
-THIS LOOKS FINE.
-AH.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
T'Pol: I'm sorry to interrupt,
Captain, but we've detected
an uncharted system
along our present course.
One of the planets
is Minshara-class.
TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
I'M ON MY WAY.
LOOKS LIKE WE'LL HAVE
TO RESCHEDULE.
WHENEVER IT'S CONVENIENT.
AFTER YOU, SIR.
ANYBODY HOME?
IT'S UNINHABITED.
WHAT ABOUT GEOGRAPHICAL
FEATURES? ANYTHING INTERESTING?
T'POL: THERE'S A CHAIN
OF VOLCANOES
THAT SPANS
AN ENTIRE HEMISPHERE.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT ANYONE ELSE,
BUT I COULD USE SOME FRESH AIR.
PUT US IN A STANDARD ORBIT.
AYE, SIR.
FIND A VOLCANO
WITH A GENTLE SLOPE,
PREFERABLY ONE
THAT'S NOT ERUPTING.
PREP A SHUTTLEPOD, TRAVIS.
WE'LL TAKE SHIFTS DOWN TO --
[ EXPLOSION ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: REPORT!
IT WAS A THERMOKINETIC EXPLOSION
ON THE OUTER HULL,
PORT-FORWARD QUARTER.
BREACHES ON "C" DECK, "D" DECK.
BRIDGE TO SICK BAY.
WE NEED MEDICAL ASSISTANCE.
-Acknowledged.
-EMERGENCY BULKHEADS?
THEY'RE IN PLACE,
BUT EIGHT SUBSECTIONS
HAVE DECOMPRESSED.
-WAS ANYBODY IN THEM?
-I CAN'T TELL, SIR, NOT YET.
FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
MALCOLM!
I'D GIVE YOU AN ANSWER
IF I COULD, SIR.
THE SENSOR LOGS
AREN'T SHOWING ANYTHING.
ALL SYSTEMS WERE
FUNCTIONING NORMALLY.
ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
CAPTAIN, WHAT'S GOING ON?
I was hoping you could tell me.
WE'VE GOT PLASMA FIRES,
AN OVERLOAD IN THE E.P.S. GRID,
BUT WHATEVER CAUSED THAT
EXPLOSION, I DON'T HAVE A CLUE.
Weapons fire? An asteroid?
NOTHING ON OUR SENSORS.
HOW ARE YOUR PEOPLE?
TUCKER: A FEW BUMPS AND BRUISES,
BUT WE'RE ALL RIGHT.
Keep me posted. Archer out.
ANY CASUALTY REPORTS?
FIGURES ARE COMING IN, SIR.
17 SO FAR, INCLUDING HOSHI.
NO FATALITIES.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
GET THIS MAN INTO
THE IMAGING CHAMBER.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
ARE WE UNDER ATTACK?
-I DON'T KNOW.
-DOCTOR!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
EASY. EASY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN.
SOMETHING JUST STRUCK THE SHIP.
STARBOARD SIDE.
UPPER-AFT QUADRANT.
CAN YOU GET A VISUAL?
THERE.
JUST BEHIND
THE SECONDARY PLASMA VENT.
YOU SEE IT?
TRAVIS: SOME KIND
OF CLOAKED SHIP?
IT'S TOO SMALL.
T'POL: I'M NOT READING
ANY BIO-SIGNS.
REED: IT'S ARMED
WITH TRICOBALT EXPLOSIVES.
I THINK IT'S A MINE.
AND JUDGING BY THE FIREPOWER,
SOMETHING SIMILAR
DAMAGED OUR SHIP.
CAN YOU TELL
IF IT'S ACTIVE?
NO REASON TO BELIEVE IT'S NOT.
T'POL: CAPTAIN, IT'S LODGED
NEAR IMPULSE REACTOR 2.
AN EXPLOSION ANYWHERE NEAR THERE
COULD DISABLE ENTERPRISE.
WHAT IF WE POLARIZED
THE ADJACENT HULL PLATING?
WE DON'T KNOW
HOW IT'S TRIGGERED.
SOMEBODY HAS TO GO OUT THERE
AND DEFUSE IT,
AND IT SHOULD BE ME.
I HAVE THE ORDNANCE TRAINING.
ARCHER: I'VE NEVER HEARD OF
A MINEFIELD
WITH JUST TWO MINES.
ARE THE QUANTUM BEACONS
STILL MOUNTED
ON THE GRAPPLER ARM?
I BELIEVE SO.
LOWER THEM INTO POSITION,
THEN MODIFY THE VIEWSCREEN.
ACTIVATE THE BEACON.
THEY WERE DESIGNED TO PENETRATE
SULIBAN CLOAKING DEVICES.
I'LL TRY SHIFTING
THE PHASE VARIANCE.
LIEUTENANT REED TO THE BRIDGE.
I'VE OPENED THE OUTER HATCH.
WISH ME LUCK.
I'M DETECTING SOMETHING
IN THE GAMMA SPECTRUM --
PHASE VARIANT .0075.
[ SIGHS ]
ITS SURFACE IS POCKMARKED.
PROBABLY MICROMETEORITE IMPACTS.
IT SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN IN ORBIT
FOR SOME TIME.
THE SPIKES ARE MAGNETIC.
TWO OF THEM HAVE LOCKED
ONTO THE HULL.
Stand by. I'm gonna run
an internal scan.
THERE ARE PROXIMITY SENSORS...
BUT THEY APPEAR TO BE OFFLINE.
It looks like the mine
doesn't think it's hit anything.
I believe I've found
an access panel.
I'm gonna try and remove it
and get a look inside.
HOW BAD IS IT?
I CAN'T REALLY TELL
UNTIL WE CAN GET INTO
THE DECOMPRESSED SECTIONS,
BUT I IMAGINE IT'S PRETTY UGLY.
I'VE GOT ONE PIECE
OF GOOD NEWS.
I DID A HEAD COUNT.
WE DIDN'T LOSE ANYONE.
TRIP, I'M NOT SURE MALCOLM'S
GONNA BE ABLE TO DEFUSE
THIS THING.
COULDN'T WE JUST DETACH
THAT SECTION OF HULL PLATING,
LET IT DRIFT AWAY?
WE'D HAVE TO REROUTE
SOME E.P.S. CONDUITS.
THERE'S ABOUT 300
BOLT COUPLINGS.
IT COULD BE DONE.
HOW LONG?
THREE OR FOUR HOURS,
BUT I WOULDN'T
RECOMMEND IT, SIR.
WE'D BE EXPOSING A GOOD PIECE
OF THE IMPULSE MANIFOLD.
GET A TEAM STARTED.
I'LL CONSIDER IT A LAST RESORT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Reed: I'm removing the panel.
THE ARMING MECHANISM'S
EXTENDING.
CAPTAIN.
WE SEE IT, MALCOLM.
ARCHER: EVER SEE
A SHIP LIKE THAT?
NO.
IT'S DEFLECTING OUR SCANS.
WHY DIDN'T THE BEACONS
LET US SEE THROUGH ITS CLOAK?
T'POL: PERHAPS THE MINES USE A
MORE PRIMITIVE CLOAKING SYSTEM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
SIR, THEY'RE HAILING US.
[ MALE SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
THE TRANSLATOR'S NOT LOCKING ON.
ARCHER TO SICK BAY.
YES, CAPTAIN.
Is Hoshi in any shape to return
to the bridge? It's urgent.
I'M AFRAID NOT. SHE SUFFERED
A RATHER SEVERE CONCUSSION.
Understood.
TELL THEM I'M ON MY WAY.
YOU'D BE OF LITTLE HELP IN YOUR
PRESENT CONDITION, ENSIGN.
[ SIGHS ]
[ MALE SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
ANY LUCK?
NOT YET.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
THEY MISSED OUR STARBOARD
NACELLE BY LESS THAN 20 METERS.
NOT A VERY SUBTLE
WARNING SHOT.
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
CAN YOU GET US OUT OF HERE?
TRAVIS: THE ORBITS OF THOSE
MINES ARE PRETTY ERRATIC, SIR.
IT'S GOING TO BE TRICKY.
WE'LL GIVE YOU
WHATEVER HELP WE CAN.
BRIDGE TO LIEUTENANT REED.
Go ahead.
OUR FRIENDS SEEM TO BE ANXIOUS
FOR US TO LEAVE.
WE'RE GOING TO BREAK ORBIT
NICE AND SLOWLY.
UNDERSTOOD.
IF YOU PLAN TO GO TO WARP, SIR,
YOU'LL LET ME KNOW?
I'll try to remember.
-MANEUVERING THRUSTERS ONLY.
-AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: ACTIVATE THE BEACON.
OUR FRIENDS JUST VANISHED.
Archer: That doesn't mean
they're not still close.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Lieutenant Reed to bridge.
GO AHEAD.
I'VE IDENTIFIED FOUR SEPARATE
DETONATION CIRCUITS.
IF I CAN ISOLATE THEM
IN THE PROPER SEQUENCE,
I SHOULD BE ABLE
TO DEACTIVATE THE MINE.
IT'LL TAKE SOME DOING.
AND TO BE HONEST, CAPTAIN,
IT'S ONLY A THEORY.
HOW GOOD A THEORY?
The closest thing
I'm familiar with
that this device resembles
is a Triton-class
spatial torpedo.
I'VE DISARMED AT LEAST
HALF A DOZEN OF THOSE.
I BELIEVE I CAN DO IT, SIR.
I'VE GOT TRIP WORKING
ON A BACKUP PLAN,
BUT I'D PREFER NOT TO USE IT.
RIGHT NOW, YOU'RE OUR BEST BET.
BE CAREFUL, MALCOLM.
I SEE IT.
AAH!
[ GROANING ]
BRIDGE.
GO AHEAD.
Another one of those spikes
I told you about.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
IT JUST MAGNETIZED ITSELF
TO THE HULL.
Is there a problem?
ON ITS WAY...
[ COUGHS ]
IT WENT THROUGH MY LEG, SIR.
I'M ON MY WAY, LIEUTENANT.
THE BRIDGE IS YOURS.
CAPTAIN, I SHOULD BE THE ONE
TO GO OUT THERE.
I'M THE ENGINEER.
THAT'S WHY I NEED YOU
HERE, TRIP.
YOU'LL HAVE TO WAIT IN LINE
FOR MY OSMOTIC EEL
TO CAUTERIZE YOUR WOUND; HE'S
GETTING QUITE A WORKOUT TODAY.
-DOCTOR.
-ENSIGN.
THEY NEED A TRANSLATOR.
I SHOULD BE AT MY POST.
I REALIZE YOU'RE
ANXIOUS TO HELP,
BUT YOU WOULDN'T MAKE IT
TO THE TURBOLIFT.
IF YOU'D LIKE, I COULD HAVE THEM
BRING THE COM LOGS HERE.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
ARCHER: THOUGHT YOU
MIGHT NEED A HAND.
ACTUALLY...I'D PREFER A LEG.
LET'S SEE WHAT WE CAN DO
WITH THE ONE YOU GOT.
COULD HAVE BEEN WORSE.
IT MISSED THE BONE.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE THE PRESSURE
FROM THE SPIKE IS
KEEPING THE WOUND
FROM BLEEDING TOO MUCH.
YOU'LL BE IN SICK BAY
IN NO TIME.
THESE SHOULD CUT
RIGHT THROUGH IT.
REED: ACTUALLY, SIR,
I WOULDN'T DO THAT.
MY SCANS SHOW DETONATION
CIRCUITS INSIDE THE SPIKES.
I WOULD CONSIDER
LETTING YOU AMPUTATE,
BUT IF CHEF GOT HOLD OF IT,
HE'D BE SERVING
ROAST REED FOR SUNDAY DINNER.
-[ CHUCKLES ]
-JUST GIVE ME
SOMETHING FOR THE PAIN,
AND I'LL DO MY BEST
TO REACH THE ACCESS PANEL.
NOT WITHOUT DOING MORE DAMAGE
TO THAT LEG.
WHAT'S MORE IMPORTANT --
MY LEG OR YOUR SHIP?
I INTEND TO SAVE BOTH.
I DON'T SEE HOW.
ARCHER: THAT BACKUP PLAN
I WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT --
I ASKED TRIP TO PREPARE
TO DETACH THIS SECTION
OF HULL PLATING.
SEEMED LIKE A GOOD IDEA
AT THE TIME.
IT'S STILL A GOOD IDEA.
NOT WITH YOU
ATTACHED TO IT.
I HOPE THAT'S AN ANESTHETIC.
PHLOX'S OWN RECIPE.
[ REED SIGHS ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
PLEASE, SIR,
MAY I HAVE SOME MORE?
ARCHER: I DON'T WANT YOU
TOO SEDATED.
I'M GONNA NEED YOUR HELP.
SOMEONE'S GOT
TO DEFUSE THIS THING.
YOU'RE GONNA TALK ME THROUGH IT.
REED: WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
CAPTAIN,
DISARMING MINES
IS EXTREMELY DELICATE BUSINESS.
I'M TRAINED FOR IT.
YOU'RE NOT.
ARCHER: I'M A QUICK STUDY.
REED: IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
ARCHER: IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T
NOTICED, LIEUTENANT,
WE'RE SITTING ABOUT FIVE METERS
FROM AN IMPULSE REACTOR.
I'M NOT LEAVING TILL
WE TAKE THIS WEAPON OFFLINE.
SIR --
THE WAY I SEE IT,
YOU DON'T HAVE MUCH CHOICE.
YOU'RE SORT OF STUCK HERE,
SO WOULD YOU
LET ME GET STARTED?
REED: I HOPE YOU'VE GOT
A STEADY HAND.
THEY'RE ORDERING US TO LEAVE
THEIR SYSTEM IMMEDIATELY,
OR THEY'LL DESTROY US.
CHARMING.
COULD YOU FIGURE OUT A WAY
TO COMPOSE A MESSAGE BACK
EXPLAINING...WE'RE GOING
AS FAST AS WE CAN?
I CAN TRY.
T'POL: AND THEIR NEXT MESSAGE?
THEY SAY THEY'VE
ANNEXED THIS PLANET
IN THE NAME OF SOMETHING CALLED
THE ROMALIN STAR EMPIRE.
T'POL: ROMULAN.
IT'S PRONOUNCED ROMULAN.
ARCHER: ROMULANS?
I READ ABOUT THEM
WHEN I WAS WITH DANIELS.
Tucker: What'd you find out?
NOT MUCH. JUST THE NAME.
H-HE WOULDN'T LET ME
SEE ANYTHING ELSE. T'POL?
T'POL: THEY'RE RUMORED TO BE AN
AGGRESSIVE, TERRITORIAL SPECIES,
BUT THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
HAS NEVER MADE
DIRECT CONTACT WITH THEM.
ENSIGN SATO'S TRANSLATION SAYS
THAT THEY'RE DEMANDING
THAT WE WITHDRAW
from this system immediately.
THAT'S GONNA BE A LITTLE
TOUGH TO DO AT THE MOMENT.
IS THERE ANY WAY YOU CAN EXPLAIN
OUR SITUATION?
SHE BELIEVES SHE'LL HAVE A REPLY
PREPARED WITHIN THE HOUR.
HOW'S IT GOING OUT THERE,
CAPTAIN?
We've taken two of
the detonation circuits offline.
Three more to go.
Keep me posted.
REED: THE NEXT ONE'S GOING
TO BE TRICKY.
DO YOU SEE
THE Y-SHAPED COMPONENTS
SURROUNDING THE CIRCUIT?
THERE'S SIX OF THEM.
REED: RIGHT.
THOSE ARE TIMING RELAYS.
YOU'LL HAVE TO ROTATE EACH ONE
COUNTERCLOCKWISE 70 DEGREES.
BUT IT HAS TO BE DONE
IN THE PROPER ORDER.
I'LL GUIDE YOU THROUGH IT.
START WITH THE RELAY
TO YOUR UPPER RIGHT.
ONE CENTIMETER.
AND THEN TURN IT 70 DEGREES
COUNTERCLOCKWISE.
GOOD.
NOW PULL IT OUT, SLOWLY.
BE CAREFUL NOT TO TOUCH
THE HOUSING.
REED: WELL DONE.
NOW COMPLETE THAT SET
ON THE DIAGONAL.
SO WHERE WERE WE?
SIR?
ARCHER: THIS MORNING
AT BREAKFAST,
BEFORE WE WERE INTERRUPTED.
YOU SAID YOU DIDN'T FOLLOW
ANY PARTICULAR SPORT.
WELL, I'M AFRAID I HAVEN'T
STARTED FOLLOWING ONE
SINCE BREAKFAST, SIR.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
REED: NOW, GO
TO THE RELAY TOP CENTER.
BUT WATCH THAT ONE.
I BELIEVE IT MAY BE DAMAGED.
IT'LL NEED SOME EXTRA TORQUE
TO DEACTIVATE IT.
HOW ABOUT HOBBIES?
ARCHER: ANY HOBBIES?
NO. NOT REALLY, SIR.
ARCHER: COULD'VE SWORN
I'VE SEEN YOU READING
A BOOK OR TWO
IN THE MESS HALL.
SIR...DO YOU REALLY THINK
THAT THIS IS THE APPROPRIATE
TIME FOR A CHAT?
IT HELPS ME FOCUS.
IT CALMS MY NERVES.
WELL, IT ISN'T CALMING MINE.
ARCHER: SORRY.
IT MADE YOU A LITTLE NERVOUS
THIS MORNING, TOO,
DIDN'T IT? WHY IS THAT?
IF YOU MUST KNOW...
I WAS HONORED TO BE ASKED
TO SIT AT YOUR TABLE.
I JUST WASN'T ENTIRELY
COMFORTABLE
HAVING A CASUAL MEAL
WITH MY CAPTAIN.
I WAS TRAINED NOT TO FRATERNIZE
WITH SUPERIOR OFFICERS.
NEVER TOO LATE TO LEARN.
FRANKLY, SIR,
FROM MY POINT OF VIEW,
THAT KIND OF SOCIALIZING HAS
NO PLACE ON A STARSHIP.
I HAD A C.O. ONCE,
FELT THE SAME WAY --
"THEY'RE YOUR CREW,
NOT YOUR FRIENDS."
I THOUGHT ABOUT THAT A LOT
WHEN I TOOK THIS COMMAND.
BUT THEN I REALIZED THIS IS NOT
YOUR TYPICAL MISSION.
ARCHER: WE COULD BE
OUT HERE FOR YEARS.
ALL WE HAVE TO DEPEND ON...
IS EACH OTHER.
[ SIGHS ]
THERE ARE TWO LEFT.
TOP LEFT FIRST.
I APPRECIATE YOUR SUGGESTIONS,
MALCOLM.
ANYTHING ELSE?
WELL...SINCE YOU ASKED...
BRIDGE PROTOCOLS
HAVE BECOME SOMEWHAT LAX.
TOO MANY PEOPLE
OFFERING OPINIONS.
WE'RE HERE TO CARRY OUT
YOUR ORDERS, SIR.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S THE POINT
OF HAVING A SENIOR STAFF
IF THEY JUST SIT AROUND
WITH THEIR MOUTHS SHUT?
GLAD THEY HAVE OPINIONS.
I RELY ON THEM.
AHH.
KEEP GOING.
AND IN THE AREA OF SECURITY,
I SOMETIMES THINK YOU COULD SHOW
A LITTLE MORE...CAUTION, SIR.
I'M AWARE OF YOUR CONCERNS
IN THAT AREA.
NOT TO SAY THAT IT
HASN'T BEEN A PRIVILEGE
TO HAVE SERVED WITH YOU.
UNH-UNH!
SIR?
ARCHER: YOU'RE TALKING
IN THE PAST TENSE, LIEUTENANT.
NOW...REINSERT ALL SIX RELAYS,
BUT IN THE REVERSE ORDER.
YOU'RE DOING FINE, SIR.
THANKS.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU'VE EARNED
YOURSELF A BREAK, TRAVIS.
ENSIGN HUTCHISON CAN COVER
THE HELM FOR A WHILE.
THANK YOU, SIR, BUT I'D PREFER
TO STAY AT MY POST.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
Archer: Go ahead.
WE'RE CLEAR OF THE MINEFIELD.
MAINTAIN COURSE AND SPEED.
Understood.
REED: THIS LAST
DETONATION CIRCUIT
HAS AN ADDED ATTRACTION.
I'M SEEING SOMETHING
THAT LOOKS LIKE
A BACKUP ARMING MECHANISM.
[ GRUNTS ]
WE'LL HAVE TO FOOL
THE CIRCUIT
INTO THINKING
IT'S STILL ONLINE.
ARCHER: HOW DO WE DO THAT?
THERE'S A HYPERSPANNER
IN THE EQUIPMENT CASE.
TAKE OUT ITS POWER CELL
AND STRIP OFF THE CASING.
ARCHER: YOU MUST HAVE REALIZED
THIS WASN'T GOING TO BE
YOUR TYPICAL ARMORY POSTING,
THAT MY...COMMAND STYLE
LACKED A CERTAIN
SPIT AND POLISH.
IT WAS OBVIOUS...
IF YOU DON'T MIND ME SAYING SO.
[ CHUCKLES ]
STRANGE.
WHAT'S STRANGE, SIR?
ARCHER: I UNDERSTAND YOU CAME
FROM A LONG LINE
OF ROYAL NAVY MEN.
YOUR FATHER, YOUR GRANDFATHER.
WHY PICK STARFLEET?
WHY NOT CONTINUE
THE FAMILY TRADITION?
GOD KNOWS I TRIED.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I'LL NEED A CIRCUIT PROBE.
[ SIGHS ]
SO WHAT HAPPENED?
I WAS RAISED ON THE WATER.
I KNEW HOW TO HANDLE A BOAT
BEFORE I COULD RIDE A BICYCLE.
STUDIED ALL
THE GREAT NAVAL BATTLES.
I DON'T KNOW.
I SUPPOSE I THOUGHT
I'D JUST GROW OUT OF IT.
GROW OUT OF WHAT?
AQUAPHOBIA.
YOU'RE AFRAID OF THE WATER?
MORE PRECISELY,
AFRAID OF DROWNING.
SO...
INSTEAD OF A LIFE
ON THE SEA, YOU CHOSE
A LIFE IN THE VACUUM OF SPACE?
[ REED SIGHS ]
I HAD A GREAT-UNCLE
WHO SUFFERED
FROM THE SAME PROBLEM...
BUT HE FACED HIS FEARS.
JOINED THE NAVY,
HAD A DISTINGUISHED CAREER.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS ATTACH IT TO THE CYLINDER
ON YOUR UPPER RIGHT.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S WORKING.
START WITH THE TOPMOST
COMPONENT.
USE THE CALIPER TO LIFT IT
A FEW MILLIMETERS,
AND THEN TURN IT
CLOCKWISE 360 DEGREES,
AND THEN GENTLY REINSERT IT.
HE WAS SOMETHING
OF A HERO TO ME,
MY GREAT-UNCLE.
THE ONE WITH AQUAPHOBIA?
REED: INDEED.
HE SIGNED UP
WITH THE SUBMARINE SERVICE.
ARCHER: TALK ABOUT FACING
YOUR DEEPEST FEARS.
HE WAS A BRAVE MAN.
WASN'T LONG BEFORE HE'D WORKED
HIS WAY UP THROUGH THE RANKS,
MADE CHIEF ENGINEER
ON THE H.M.S. CLEMENT.
DO YOU KNOW THE STORY
OF THE CLEMENT, SIR?
I DON'T THINK I DO.
REED: GOOD.
NOW...THE OTHER FIVE
COMPONENTS.
REPEAT THE SAME PROCESS
ON EACH ONE,
COUNTERCLOCKWISE.
YOU WERE TELLING ME
ABOUT THE CLEMENT.
THEY WERE ON A ROUTINE PATROL
WHEN THEY HAD AN ACCIDENT.
NOW, THERE'S A BEAUTIFUL IRONY
FOR YOU.
THEY HIT A MINE...
LEFT OVER FROM SOME WORLD WAR.
REED: THERE THEY WERE,
TRAPPED UNDERNEATH AN ICE SHELF,
SEVERAL COMPARTMENTS FLOODING,
INCLUDING ENGINEERING.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
MY GREAT-UNCLE...
THE MAN AFRAID OF DROWNING.
REED: THE SHIP WAS SINKING,
LOSING POWER.
ACCORDING TO HIS LIEUTENANT...
MY GREAT-UNCLE SEALED HIMSELF
IN THE ENGINE ROOM
AND KEPT THE REACTOR ONLINE
LONG ENOUGH
FOR HIS CREW TO MAKE IT
TO THE ESCAPE PODS.
HE WENT DOWN WITH HIS SHIP.
HE DID WHAT HE HAD TO DO
TO SAVE HIS CREWMATES.
I APPRECIATE WHAT YOU'RE TRYING
TO TELL ME, MALCOLM...
BUT I WAS HOPING...
YOU'D BE ABLE TO SAVE
YOUR HEROICS FOR ANOTHER TIME.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW, SIR,
THAT I AM PREPARED.
GOT YOU.
IF WE'RE NOT ABLE
TO DEFUSE THIS MINE,
THE SAFETY OF THE CREW
HAS TO --
I SAID I HEARD YOU, LIEUTENANT.
I'M AFRAID WE HAVE
ANOTHER PROBLEM, SIR.
WHAT? WHAT IS IT?
I NEED TO USE THE BATHROOM.
I WON'T TELL A SOUL.
IN MY E.V. SUIT, SIR?
[ LAUGHTER ]
SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
YOU'VE IGNORED OUR WARNINGS.
WE WERE UNABLE
TO TRANSLATE YOUR LANGUAGE
UNTIL A SHORT TIME AGO.
WE'RE TRYING TO DEFUSE A WEAPON
LODGED ON OUR HULL.
I'M WELL AWARE
OF YOUR SITUATION.
OUR SCANS SHOW YOU'RE PREPARED
TO DETACH THE HULL SEGMENT
SURROUNDING THE MINE.
COMPLETE THE PROCEDURE
AND LEAVE THIS SYSTEM
IMMEDIATELY.
WE'VE GOT A MAN
TRAPPED OUT THERE.
DON'T YOUR SCANS SHOW YOU THAT?
ONE CREWMAN.
YOU HAVE 82 OTHERS
SAFELY ABOARD.
JETTISON THE HULL SEGMENT
AND LEAVE.
WE WILL NOT TOLERATE ESPIONAGE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Archer: T'Pol, report.
THEY'RE DEMANDING
THAT WE JETTISON THE SECTION
OF THE HULL PLATING AND LEAVE.
THEY SCANNED US, CAPTAIN.
THEY KNOW WE'RE READY
TO DETACH IT.
ARCHER: I'M DEFUSING
THE LAST DETONATION CIRCUIT.
STAND BY.
IT'S REARMING!
REED: RESET THAT LAST COMPONENT!
QUICKLY!
LIEUTENANT?
WHEN YOU DEACTIVATED
THAT FINAL CIRCUIT,
IT TRIGGERED A SUB-DETONATOR.
HOW CAN WE GET TO IT?
WE CAN'T.
IT'S TOO DEEP INSIDE.
WE'D HAVE TO DISMANTLE
THE ENTIRE MINE.
REED: CAPTAIN...
THOSE HEROICS WE SPOKE ABOUT.
I THINK IT MAY BE TIME.
YOU'VE DONE ALL YOU CAN, SIR.
FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH,
YOU'D MAKE A FINE
ARMORY OFFICER.
SHOW ME THAT SUB-DETONATOR.
REED: I'D PREFER
A BURIAL AT SEA
IF I'M NOT
COMPLETELY VAPORIZED.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT YOU WERE
AFRAID OF THE WATER.
YOUR SCANNER, LIEUTENANT.
I TOLD YOU, SIR.
THERE'S NOTHING WE CAN DO.
WE'LL DISMANTLE THIS THING
PIECE BY PIECE IF WE HAVE TO.
THAT'LL TAKE DAYS.
MY SCHEDULE'S OPEN.
REED: AND THESE ROMULANS --
THEY DON'T SEEM
LIKE THE PATIENT TYPES.
REED: THE LONGER WE STAY
IN THIS SYSTEM,
THE MORE LIKELY
THEY'RE GOING TO ATTACK.
AS MUCH AS I APPRECIATE
ALL YOUR EFFORTS,
YOU HAVE TO DETACH
THE HULL PLATING.
IT'S THE ONLY OPTION.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO LEAVE
ONE OF MY CREW BEHIND.
YOU'RE PUTTING ENTERPRISE
AT RISK.
ARCHER: WE'RE WASTING TIME!
HELP ME FIGURE OUT A WAY
TO GET YOU OFF OF HERE.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ AIR HISSING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
ARCHER: GREAT.
[ AIR HISSES ]
IF I WERE THE KIND OF CAPTAIN
YOU THINK I SHOULD BE,
I'D BUST YOUR ASS
BACK TO CREWMAN.
BEGGING YOUR PARDON, SIR,
BUT IF YOU WERE
THAT KIND OF CAPTAIN,
WE WOULDN'T BE HAVING
THIS CONVERSATION.
YOU'D HAVE CUT ME LOOSE BY NOW.
I'M NOT GONNA DO THAT, MALCOLM.
WHEN WE TRIGGERED
THAT SUB-DETONATOR,
WHY DIDN'T THE MINE
EXPLODE RIGHT AWAY?
HOW MANY SECONDS WENT BY
BEFORE I REARMED IT?
-SIR?
-HOW MANY SECONDS?
I DON'T REMEMBER.
10, MAYBE 12.
ARCHER: IT FELT MORE LIKE 20.
10, 20 -- WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
ARCHER: IF IT HAD EXPLODED...
HOW BIG WOULD
THE YIELD HAVE BEEN?
REED: JUDGING BY THE DAMAGE
THE FIRST MINE CAUSED,
I'D GUESS ABOUT A QUARTER
OF A KILOTON.
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT, SIR?
ARCHER: HOW CLOSE IS YOUR TEAM
TO FINISHING?
TUCKER: THEY'RE DOWN TO
THE LAST FEW COUPLINGS.
WHAT'S GOING ON OUT THERE?
ARCHER: WE'RE GONNA
DETACH THE PLATING.
I'M SURE YOU DID EVERYTHING
YOU COULD, CAPTAIN --
I'M GOING WITH HIM.
COULD A SHUTTLEPOD HATCH
WITHSTAND
A QUARTER-KILOTON BLAST?
DEPENDS HOW CLOSE IT WAS.
20 METERS, MAYBE 25.
YEAH, THEY'RE REINFORCED
WITH DURITANIUM ALLOY.
THEY CAN TAKE A HELL
OF A BEATING.
WHAT DO YOU GOT IN MIND?
I NEED TWO SHUTTLEPOD HATCHES.
HAVE THEM BROUGHT UP HERE
ON THE DOUBLE.
-SIR?
-ON THE DOUBLE.
CAPTAIN, I ASSUME
THERE'S NO POINT
IN MY QUESTIONING YOUR PLAN.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
-GO AHEAD.
-We're ready.
SEE YOU SOON.
HANG ON, FELLAS.
[ WHIRRING ]
600 METERS.
TUCKER: ANOTHER HUNDRED
OUGHT TO DO IT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
SUBCOMMANDER.
HAIL THEM.
NO RESPONSE.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS!
T'POL: POLARIZE
THE HULL PLATING.
I'LL DO WHAT I CAN,
BUT KEEP IN MIND
WE'RE MISSING SOME OF IT.
REED: IT'S REARMING!
ARCHER: THAT'S IT. LET'S GO.
NOW, MALCOLM!
ENTERPRISE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
T'POL: CAPTAIN, RESPOND.
MAYBE THEIR TRANSMITTERS WERE
KNOCKED OUT IN THE BLAST.
TRAVIS?
I SEE THEM.
BEARING 213 MARK 4.
CLOSING IN.
T'POL: OPEN THE DOORS
TO LAUNCH BAY 2.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
THE ROMULANS
ARE LOCKING WEAPONS!
-BRIDGE TO DR. PHLOX.
-Go ahead.
MEET US OUTSIDE LAUNCH BAY 2.
TUCKER: THEY'RE
TARGETING OUR ENGINES!
100 METERS MORE.
50.
I'VE GOT THEM.
SEALING LAUNCH BAY DOORS.
GO TO WARP, ENSIGN.
[ PANTING ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
UH-HUH, ALL THINGS
CONSIDERED.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
IF I MAY SAY SO, SIR,
YOUR STYLE OF COMMAND
DOES HAVE ITS ADVANTAGES.
SO, HOW LONG WAS IT?
[ GRUNTING ]
I COUNTED 10 SECONDS.
10? IT WAS MORE LIKE 20.
RESPECTFULLY, SIR, IT WAS 10.
I'M NOT GONNA ARGUE
WITH YOU, MALCOLM.
IT WAS 20.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HEY.
COME ON.