[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
MAN: I NEED
THREE MORE CONTAINERS.
BRING THEM TO ME.
SECOND MAN: YEAH.
THIRD MAN: WE HAVE TWO TYPES.
FOURTH MAN: I'M ON IT.
WE'RE DOWN 22%. TELL HIM.
[ AIRCRAFT APPROACHING ]
IS IT THEM?
MAN: I DON'T KNOW.
NO.
IT'S NOT THEIR SHIP.
IT'S SOMEONE ELSE.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER:
MY NAME IS CAPTAIN ARCHER
FROM THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
WE TRIED TO HAIL YOU,
BUT THERE WAS NO RESPONSE.
FIRST MAN: OUR COMMUNICATIONS
ARE DOWN.
THAT MUST MAKE IT DIFFICULT
TO DO BUSINESS.
A KREETASSAN MERCHANT TOLD US
THIS WAS A DEUTERIUM FACILITY.
FIRST MAN: HE WAS CORRECT.
TUCKER: OUR SHIP TOOK
SOME DAMAGE A FEW WEEKS AGO.
WE LOST MOST OF OUR RESERVES.
FIRST MAN: I'M SORRY,
BUT WE CAN'T HELP YOU.
TWO OF OUR PUMPS ARE OFFLINE.
YOU'LL HAVE TO RETURN
LATER IN THE SEASON.
OUR SUPPLY WILL BE GONE
IN LESS THAN TWO WEEKS.
THERE'S NOTHING WE CAN DO.
ARE YOU CERTAIN?
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
A LARGE INVENTORY.
OUR SENSORS SHOWED
OVER 80,000 LITERS.
YOU SCANNED OUR TANKS?
I APOLOGIZE, BUT WHEN YOU DIDN'T
RESPOND TO OUR HAILS...
YOU SURE YOU COULDN'T SPARE
A FEW HUNDRED LITERS?
FIRST MAN: WE'RE HOLDING THAT
FOR SOMEONE ELSE.
COME BACK AT THE END
OF THE SEASON.
I'M SURE WE'LL BE ABLE
TO ACCOMMODATE YOU.
SECOND MAN: DO YOU HAVE
ANY EXPERIENCE
REPAIRING EXTRACTION PUMPS?
TUCKER: NOT SPECIFICALLY,
BUT I COULD GRAB SOME TOOLS
AND TAKE A LOOK.
SECOND MAN: IF WE
GET THOSE PUMPS OPERATING,
WE CAN MAKE OUR QUOTA.
IT SEEMS THAT THERE
MIGHT BE AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR US TO HELP EACH OTHER.
FIRST MAN: FOLLOW ME.
[ BOY IMITATES EXPLOSIONS ]
[ MACHINE BEEPS ]
[ BOY GASPS ]
TUCKER: WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN MY CHAIR?
BOY: UM, I--I DIDN'T
TOUCH ANYTHING.
I JUST LIKE TO LOOK
INSIDE THE SHIPS THAT COME HERE.
TUCKER: WELL,
YOU SHOULD'VE ASKED.
BOY: YOU MIGHT HAVE SAID NO.
WELL...
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WELL, IT'S A LITTLE SMALL,
AND YOUR THRUSTER CONTROLS
ARE HARD TO REACH.
OH. WELL, MAYBE YOU NEED
LONGER ARMS.
HOW FAST CAN IT GO?
SHE'S DESIGNED
FOR ONE-QUARTER IMPULSE,
BUT, UH, I'VE BEEN
ABLE TO SQUEEZE
A LITTLE MORE OUT OF HER.
BOY: YOU'RE A PILOT?
TUCKER: ENGINEER.
COMMANDER TRIP TUCKER.
Q'ELL.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
COULD YOU TEACH ME
HOW TO FLY IT?
[ CHUCKLES ]
I CAN DRIVE THE CRAWLER THAT
WE USE TO MOVE OUR DRILL RIGS.
TELL YOU WHAT.
I'LL BE HEADING BACK UP
TO THE SHIP LATER.
YOU CAN COME ALONG IF IT'S
ALL RIGHT WITH YOUR FOLKS.
I'LL GIVE YOU A TOUR.
REALLY?
FIRST MAN: TWO POWER CELLS...
WE NEED SIX.
ARCHER: WE CAN'T SPARE
THAT MANY.
MAYBE THREE.
FIRST MAN: DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
HOW MUCH LABOR IT TAKES
TO REFINE A LITER OF DEUTERIUM?
ARCHER: ACTUALLY, NO.
I'D ENJOY SEEING
HOW YOUR FACILITY WORKS.
WE HAVE THREE MONTHS
OF GOOD WEATHER, CAPTAIN--
THREE MONTHS TO PUMP
ALL THE DEUTERIUM WE CAN
BEFORE THE WINTER.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
TO GIVE TOURS.
FIVE POWER CELLS FOR 200 LITERS.
I CAN'T DO ANY BETTER.
OUR MEDICAL STORES
ARE RUNNING LOW.
ARCHER: FOUR POWER CELLS
AND WHATEVER MEDICAL SUPPLIES
WE CAN SPARE.
ALL RIGHT.
BUT ONLY
IF YOU CAN REPAIR OUR PUMPS.
COMMANDER TUCKER AND HIS TEAM
WILL DO THE BEST THEY CAN.
I EXPECT YOU TO LEAVE ORBIT
IN TWO DAYS.
IF THE PUMPS ARE WORKING, YOU'LL
LEAVE WITH YOUR DEUTERIUM.
IF NOT, YOU'LL LEAVE WITHOUT IT.
ARE WE AGREED?
AGREED.
PHLOX: IT'S YOURS,
IF YOU'D LIKE IT.
I WOULDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO FEED IT.
[ PHLOX CHUCKLES ]
PHLOX: HER NEEDS ARE MODEST--
A NUTRIENT BROTH
EVERY THREE OR FOUR DAYS...
LESS OFTEN
WHEN SHE'S WORKING.
WOMAN: WORKING?
SHE'LL INGEST A LITTLE BLOOD
WHILE SHE'S HEALING
AN INJURED ARTERY.
THANK YOU, BUT I'LL JUST TAKE
SOME VASCULAR ADHESIVE.
PHLOX: UH, TRY THIS,
HMM, INSTEAD?
AN AUTO-SUTURE.
HMM. I'M SURPRISED
YOU DON'T HAVE ONE.
THIS IS A VERY EXPENSIVE
PIECE OF EQUIPMENT. I CAN'T--
PHLOX: NONSENSE. PLEASE.
CARDIO-STIMULATOR,
NEURAL-SHOCK KIT. HUH.
I HAD NO IDEA
PROCESSING DEUTERIUM
WAS SUCH A DANGEROUS BUSINESS.
IT CAN BE.
I'VE, UH, ONLY HEARD
OF HEXATRIOL BEING USED
TO TREAT SERIOUS PLASMA BURNS.
DEUTERIUM CAN BURN
ALMOST AS HOT AS PLASMA
WHEN IT'S IGNITED.
I HOPE YOU WON'T NEED IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG?
NO.
I'D BETTER GET BACK.
OF COURSE.
THANK YOU AGAIN.
ARCHER: YOU'VE BEEN
TO OTHER COLONIES
THAT TRADE DEUTERIUM,
HAVEN'T YOU?
T'POL: SEVERAL.
ARCHER: ARE THEY ALL
THIS RUSTIC?
T'POL: NOT USUALLY.
ARCHER: THEIR EQUIPMENT'S
FALLING APART.
HALF THESE STRUCTURES LOOK LIKE
THEY'RE ABOUT TO COLLAPSE.
PHLOX TELLS ME THEY DON'T EVEN
HAVE BASIC MEDICAL SUPPLIES.
DEUTERIUM IS
A HIGHLY VALUABLE COMMODITY.
YOU'D THINK THESE PEOPLE
WOULD BE BETTER OFF.
T'POL: WE'RE HERE
TO TRADE WITH THEM,
NOT JUDGE
THEIR LIVING CONDITIONS.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
ARCHER: THEN WHY DO THEY NEED US
TO FINISH FIXING THEIR PUMPS
IN TWO DAYS?
WHAT'S THE HURRY?
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
MAYWEATHER: LIEUTENANT, A SHIP
JUST DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
600,000 KILOMETERS AND CLOSING.
I SEE HER.
HOSHI: IT'S PROBABLY
MORE DEUTERIUM CUSTOMERS.
I'M READING 12 BIO-SIGNS,
ALL KLINGON.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
TUCKER: YOU'LL WANT TO KEEP
AN EYE ON THOSE PHASE INVERTERS.
THEY TEND TO DEPOLARIZE.
[ INTERCOM BUZZING ]
SECOND MAN: PUMP SIX.
First man: Korok's ship
is entering orbit.
SECOND MAN: I THOUGHT WE HAD
THREE MORE DAYS.
First man: Secure the pumps.
Get everyone inside.
TUCKER: SOME KIND OF TROUBLE?
SECOND MAN: HELP ME CLOSE
THESE INDUCTION VALVES.
TUCKER: WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHO'S KOROK?
THEY MUST REALIZE THAT
YOU TRADE WITH OTHER SHIPS.
FIRST MAN: THEY BELIEVE THAT WE
HAVE AN EXCLUSIVE ARRANGEMENT.
WOMAN: IF THEY THINK ANYONE'S
BEEN HERE BEFORE THEM,
THEY GET VERY ANGRY.
FIRST MAN: PLEASE,
DON'T GET INVOLVED.
WE'LL TALK TO THEM.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
Reed: Go ahead, Captain.
HAVE THE KLINGONS
DETECTED ENTERPRISE YET?
NO INDICATION, SIR.
ARCHER: TRAVIS,
ADJUST YOUR ORBIT.
KEEP ENTERPRISE OUT OF SIGHT.
AYE, SIR.
KOROK: MY OLD FRIEND.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WE WEREN'T EXPECTING YOU
SO SOON.
WE'VE HAD TROUBLE
WITH TWO OF OUR PUMPS.
KOROK: MY CREW'S HUNGRY.
LET'S HAVE FOOD AND DRINK.
THEN WE'LL DISCUSS BUSINESS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
YOUR DEUTERIUM--
WE DON'T HAVE ALL OF IT.
WE DID OUR BEST,
BUT WE NEED MORE TIME.
TUCKER: CAN YOU MAKE OUT
WHAT THEY'RE SAYING?
T'POL: TESSIC IS EXPLAINING
THAT THEIR YIELD
ISN'T WHAT THEY'D HOPED.
TUCKER: GOOD EARS.
TESSIC: ...MAKE ANY DIFFERENCE.
WITHOUT THOSE PUMPS, WE COULDN'T
OPERATE AT FULL CAPACITY.
I SENSE WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO SAY
IS NOT GOING TO MAKE ME HAPPY.
WE CAN GIVE YOU
80,000 LITERS.
IF YOU'LL GIVE US ONE MORE WEEK,
WE'LL HAVE THE REST.
KOROK: YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH TIME.
WE'LL TAKE ALL OF IT, NOW!
WE DON'T HAVE IT.
I TOLD YOU, TWO PUMPS WERE DOWN.
KOROK: THEY ALL
APPEAR TO BE WORKING.
WE WERE JUST ABLE
TO REPAIR THEM.
-YOU'RE LYING!
-UGH!
SECOND MAN: LEAVE HIM ALONE.
YOU'LL GET YOUR DEUTERIUM.
UGH!
TESSIC: WAIT, PLEASE.
I CAN GET DEUTERIUM ANYWHERE.
I COME HERE
BECAUSE I LIKE YOU...
WHEN YOU SHOW ME
HOSPITALITY AND RESPECT.
SECOND MAN: YOU TAKE
EVERYTHING WE OWN,
AND YOU WANT US TO RESPECT YOU.
I'LL GIVE YOU FOUR DAYS.
HAVE IT ALL READY.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
WOMAN: LET'S GET HIM INSIDE.
ARCHER: SO THIS IS YOUR
EXCLUSIVE ARRANGEMENT?
TESSIC: IT'S NOT YOUR CONCERN.
TUCKER: HOW LONG HAVE THESE
BULLIES BEEN PUSHING YOU AROUND?
SECOND MAN: FIVE SEASONS.
THEY TAKE ALL THE FIRST-YIELD
DEUTERIUM WE CAN EXTRACT.
WOMAN: HOLD STILL.
SECOND MAN: AFTER THEY LEAVE,
WE MANAGE TO PULL A FEW THOUSAND
LITERS OUT OF THE DEEP STRATA,
BUT IT TAKES WEEKS,
AND IT'S SO FULL OF IMPURITIES
WE CAN BARELY REFINE IT.
TESSIC: IT STILL BRINGS IN
A DECENT PRICE.
WE MAKE ENOUGH TO GET
THROUGH THE WINTER.
SECOND MAN: BARELY.
T'POL: HAVE YOU TRIED CONTACTING
YOUR HOMEWORLD?
IT'S TOO FAR AWAY.
TUCKER: YOU MUST HAVE WEAPONS,
SOME WAY TO DEFEND YOURSELVES.
HOW MANY OF THEM ARE THERE?
USUALLY SEVEN.
TUCKER: SEVEN?
YOU'VE GOT THEM OUTNUMBERED
NINE OR TEN TO ONE.
TESSIC: YOU'VE NEVER SEEN
A KLINGON IN BATTLE, HAVE YOU?
WE TRIED TO STAND UP TO THEM
ONCE, THREE SEASONS AGO.
FIVE OF US DIED FIGHTING THEM.
AND THEN THEY KILLED THREE MORE
TO PROVE THEIR POINT.
ONE OF THEM WAS HIS FATHER.
ARCHER: MAYBE THERE'S SOMETHING
WE CAN DO.
JUST TAKE YOUR 200 LITERS
AND GO.
IF YOU'RE HERE WHEN THEY
COME BACK, THEY'LL KILL YOU.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: MR. REED?
Reed: The Klingon ship's
gone to warp, sir.
I'm sending a shuttlepod down.
ARCHER: WE'LL BE AT
THE LANDING SITE.
MAN: THE PRESSURE'S STEADY
AT 8.07.
CHECK UP AT THE TOP.
TUCKER: I'LL CATCH UP WITH YOU
LATER, CAPTAIN.
SORRY I NEVER GOT
TO GIVE YOU THAT TOUR.
I ONCE SAW A KELLENITE SHIP
WITH CANNONS AND TORPEDOES.
YEAH. MOST BIG SHIPS
CARRY WEAPONS.
LIKE ENTERPRISE.
YEAH, LIKE ENTERPRISE.
YOU COULD HAVE FOUGHT
THE KLINGONS, BEATEN THEM.
MAYBE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TRY?
[ SIGHS ]
IT'S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
T'POL: THE DEUTERIUM'S
BEEN STOWED--200 LITERS.
SHOULD I INSTRUCT
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER
TO BREAK ORBIT?
ARCHER: SO THAT'S IT?
WE JUST TAKE OUR DEUTERIUM
AND LEAVE?
THEY WORK THEIR ASSES OFF
TO PROVIDE FOR THEIR FAMILIES,
AND THEN THE KLINGONS JUST
STROLL IN AND ROB THEM BLIND.
DOES THAT SEEM RIGHT TO YOU?
MALCOLM TELLS ME
THAT KLINGON SHIP
ISN'T MUCH MORE
THAN A FREIGHTER.
I'D LAY ODDS THEY'RE
NO MATCH FOR ENTERPRISE.
AND IF THEY WITHDRAW?
WHAT WILL KEEP THEM FROM COMING
BACK AFTER WE'VE GONE?
WE COULD TRY TO CONTACT
THE KLINGON HIGH COUNCIL.
WE SAVED KLAANG
FROM THE SULIBAN.
WE PULLED ONE OF THEIR BATTLE
CRUISERS OUT OF A GAS GIANT.
I SAY THEY OWE US A FAVOR.
I DOUBT THESE MARAUDERS
ANSWER TO THE HIGH COUNCIL.
I ALREADY KNOW
WHERE VULCANS STAND
ON INTERFERING
WITH OTHER CULTURES,
BUT THIS ISN'T A CULTURE.
76 SETTLERS
ARE BEING PREYED UPON.
IF THIS WERE AN EARTH COLONY,
I'D BE GRATEFUL IF SOMEONE
SHOWED UP TO GIVE ME A HAND.
CAPTAIN, THIS MAY SURPRISE YOU,
BUT I AGREE.
HOWEVER,
SHORT OF KILLING THE KLINGONS,
ANY ACTION WE TAKE WILL ONLY
MAKE THE SITUATION WORSE.
I JUST HATE THE IDEA
OF TURNING OUR BACKS.
[ TESSIC GRUNTS ]
ARCHER: NEED A HAND?
TESSIC: CONTROL ARM IS JAMMED.
I COULD USE SOME HELP
WITH THE RELEASE VALVE.
ARCHER: OK.
TESSIC: TURN IT TO THE LEFT.
ARCHER: THIS ONE?
TESSIC: THOUGHT YOU'D BE OFF
CHARTING YOUR NEXT STAR SYSTEM
BY NOW.
ARCHER: SOMETIMES I HAVE A BAD
HABIT OF OVERSTAYING MY WELCOME.
WELL, YOU OBVIOUSLY
DIDN'T COME DOWN HERE
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
TO HELP ME WITH THIS CRAWLER.
ARCHER: SEEMS TO ME THIS CRAWLER
IS THE LEAST OF YOUR PROBLEMS.
TESSIC: WE'VE BEEN
THROUGH THIS BEFORE.
IT'S NOT YOUR CONCERN.
GIVE IT ANOTHER TURN.
YOU SAID THEY'VE BEEN
COMING HERE FOR, WHAT,
FIVE SEASONS?
HOW MUCH LONGER DO YOU PLAN
ON LETTING THIS GO ON,
ANOTHER FIVE?
THAT'S GOOD.
LEAVE IT THERE.
TESSIC: RECONNECT
THIS COOLANT LINE.
THE INTAKE'S ABOVE YOUR HEAD.
I HAD A TALK WITH
MY TACTICAL OFFICER.
WE'RE CONFIDENT YOU HAVE THE
ABILITY TO DEFEND YOURSELVES.
WE ALREADY TRIED.
THERE ARE EIGHT PEOPLE
BURIED NOT FAR FROM HERE
WHO CAN ATTEST TO THAT.
IT WOULD BE DIFFERENT THIS TIME.
WE WOULD HELP YOU PREPARE.
I DON'T WANT YOUR HELP.
I'M RESPONSIBLE FOR MY PEOPLE,
NOT YOU.
THEY PUT THEIR TRUST IN ME.
THEY DEPEND ON ME.
I'M SUPPOSED TO PROTECT THEM!
TESSIC: LOOK AT ME.
I CAN BARELY KEEP
THIS CRAWLER RUNNING.
YOU SAY YOU AND YOUR TACTICAL
OFFICER WANT TO HELP US.
EVEN IF YOU DO, ONCE YOU'RE
GONE, WE'LL BE ALONE AGAIN,
WAITING FOR THEM TO COME BACK.
THERE'S A SAYING ON MY WORLD.
GIVE A MAN A FISH,
AND HE EATS FOR A DAY;
TEACH HIM TO FISH,
AND HE EATS FOR A LIFETIME.
REED: I WAS HOPING FOR
A BIT MORE TO WORK WITH.
SECOND MAN: THEY DO A DECENT JOB
KEEPING THE  SHIB'A LIZARDS
FROM CHEWING ON
THE POWER COUPLINGS.
WITH A FEW MODIFICATIONS,
THESE SHOULD BE EFFECTIVE
AGAINST MORE THAN LIZARDS.
YOU MUST HAVE A WELL-STOCKED
ARMORY ONBOARD ENTERPRISE.
BUT THIS BATTLE
WON'T BE WON WITH FIREPOWER.
DECEPTION AND SURPRISE CAN BE
JUST AS POTENT AS BRUTE FORCE.
KLINGONS ARE
AGGRESSIVE WARRIORS,
BUT THEIR TACTICS ARE CRUDE.
THEY'RE SLOW TO ADAPT
TO CHANGING CIRCUMSTANCES.
TESSIC: THIS ALL SOUNDS
VERY AMBITIOUS.
WHAT EXACTLY ARE YOU
EXPECTING US TO DO?
ARCHER: YOU'RE GOING
TO LURE THEM INTO A TRAP.
WHAT KIND OF TRAP?
TUCKER: A VERY HOT ONE.
THE DEUTERIUM
IN THOSE WELLHEADS--
HOW MUCH PRESSURE IS IT UNDER,
3,000, 4,000 MILLIBARS?
5,000.
TUCKER: SHOULD CREATE
SOME INTERESTING FIREWORKS.
TESSIC: YOU'LL NEVER
GET THE KLINGONS NEAR
THAT DEUTERIUM FIELD.
THEY KNOW IT ISN'T SAFE.
SECOND MAN: THEY MAY BE CRUDE,
BUT THEY'RE NOT FOOLS.
THAT'S WHERE DECEPTION
AND SURPRISE COME IN.
DID YOU BRING THE MAP
I ASKED YOU FOR?
TESSIC: IT'S RIGHT HERE.
ARCHER: THE STRUCTURES
IN THE COLONY--
THEY'RE MOSTLY MODULAR, RIGHT?
THEY'RE ALL MODULAR.
MOST DEUTERIUM FIELDS
ARE DEPLETED
WITHIN THREE OR FOUR YEARS
AT MOST,
FORCES US TO BE ITINERANT.
SO YOU'RE SAYING YOU COULD
RELOCATE THESE BUILDINGS
IN A RELATIVELY SHORT TIME?
SECOND MAN: IT DEPENDS.
WHERE ARE YOU SUGGESTING
WE RELOCATE THEM?
ARCHER: ABOUT 50 METERS
TO THE SOUTH, RIGHT HERE.
WHAT GOOD WOULD THAT DO?
THE TERRAIN THERE
IS NO DIFFERENT
THAN WHERE THE TOWN IS NOW.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE COUNTING ON.
IF WE CAN MOVE
THE STRUCTURES AND THE RIGS,
EVERYTHING SHOULD LOOK PRETTY
MUCH LIKE IT DID YESTERDAY.
EVERYTHING EXCEPT THE WELLHEADS.
THEY'LL HAVE TO BE
CAPPED OFF AND CAMOUFLAGED.
WE CAN DO THAT.
REED: THE GULLIES
ON THIS HILLSIDE--
ARE THEY DEEP ENOUGH TO HIDE IN?
IF YOU KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN.
T'POL: WE'LL SHUTTLE
SMALL GROUPS TO ENTERPRISE
FOR WHATEVER TRAINING
WE HAVE TIME FOR,
PREFERABLY PEOPLE WHO HAVE
EXPERIENCE WITH WEAPONS.
ARCHER: WE'VE GOT THREE DAYS.
WE SHOULD GET TO WORK.
TESSIC: WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
TUCKER: ONE MORE METER.
OK, SHUT HER DOWN.
REED: YOU READY?
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
REED: AND BEGIN.
SECOND MAN: SHIB'A LIZARDS
DON'T MOVE THAT FAST.
HOSHI: DO YOU MIND, LIEUTENANT?
REED: UH-UH.
HOSHI: I CAN SEE YOUR FINGER
TENSING ON THE TRIGGER
BEFORE YOU FIRE.
IT'S THROWING OFF YOUR AIM.
I USED TO MAKE THE SAME MISTAKE.
KEEP YOUR EYE ON THE TARGET,
AND DON'T SQUEEZE THE TRIGGER
UNTIL YOU HAVE A CLEAR SHOT.
HOSHI: TRY AGAIN.
TUCKER: I THINK THE TABLE
WAS A LITTLE BIT TO THE LEFT.
ARCHER: HEH. THANKS.
HOW ARE THINGS GOING
WITH THE PUMPS?
TUCKER: AH, IT'LL BE TOMORROW
BEFORE THEY'RE ALL IN PLACE.
WE'VE STARTED
CAPPING OFF THE HEADS.
ARCHER: LET ME KNOW--I GOT IT.
THANKS--
IF YOU NEED MORE PEOPLE.
I RIGGED TWO IGNITION SEQUENCES.
THE PERIMETER AND THE CENTER
ARE ON SEPARATE CIRCUITS.
TUCKER: I THOUGHT TAKING
THE TOWN APART WAS TOUGH.
BUT PUTTING IT BACK TOGETHER...
THIS PLAN IS A LONG SHOT,
ISN'T IT?
YOU THINK IT'S A MISTAKE?
I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
I'VE NEVER LIKED BULLIES,
TRIP--
NOT ON EARTH,
AND NOT OUT HERE.
T'POL: KLINGONS
CARRY DISRUPTERS,
BUT THEY PREFER TO USE
BLADED WEAPONS IN COMBAT,
THE TWO MOST COMMON
BEING THE BAT'LETH,
A CURVED, BILATERAL SWORD,
AND THE MEK'LETH,
A TWO-PRONGED DAGGER.
THE BAT'LETH
CAN DECAPITATE ITS VICTIM
WITH ONE STROKE,
WHILE THE MEK'LETH
IS TYPICALLY USED
TO SLASH THE THROAT
OR DISEMBOWEL.
I CANNOT TEACH YOU
TO DEFEND YOURSELVES
AGAINST THESE WEAPONS.
THE VULCAN MARTIAL ART,
SUUS MAHNA,
TAKES YEARS TO MASTER.
HOWEVER, I CAN TEACH YOU
A SIMPLE EVASIVE TECHNIQUE.
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER.
SINCE I DON'T
HAVE A BAT'LETH,
THIS WILL HAVE TO SUFFICE.
TRY TO STRIKE ME.
YOU WON'T HURT ME.
MAYWEATHER: IT'S NOT YOU
THAT I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
THAT WAS CALLED
THE NAVORKOT.
IT ISN'T DIFFICULT TO LEARN.
WHO WOULD LIKE TO TRY FIRST?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
TUCKER: THANKS.
Q'ELL: LIEUTENANT REED SAID
I'D HAVE TO HIDE IN THE CANYONS
WHEN THE KLINGONS COME BACK.
UH-HUH. HE DOESN'T WANT YOU
TO GET HURT.
BUT I WANT TO HELP.
I CAN SHOOT A SHIB'A LIZARD
FROM 40 METERS.
MALCOLM'S GOT THIS RULE--
YOU'VE GOT TO BE TALLER
THAN THE GUN TO USE IT.
I DON'T WANT TO HIDE.
[ SIGHS ]
WELL...SHOOTING AT A LIZARD
IS A WHOLE LOT DIFFERENT
THAN SHOOTING AT A PERSON.
AND, UH...
LIZARDS DON'T SHOOT BACK.
WHEN THOSE KLINGONS SHOW UP,
I WANT YOU TO DO EXACTLY
WHAT LIEUTENANT REED SAYS.
UNDERSTOOD?
YES, SIR.
[ TARGETS BEEPING ]
ARCHER: WE HAD A LITTLE TROUBLE
MOVING ONE OF THE PUMPS,
BUT IT'S IN PLACE NOW.
WE'RE READY.
I JUST HOPE EVERYONE
SURVIVES THIS.
YOUR PEOPLE AS WELL AS MINE.
WE LEFT EARTH
JUST OVER A YEAR AGO
TO EXPLORE,
TO MEET PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
WE'D ONLY BEEN OUT
OF SPACEDOCK FOR THREE DAYS
WHEN WE FOUND OURSELVES
IN A FULL-FLEDGED FIREFIGHT
WITH SOME PRETTY NASTY
CHARACTERS CALLED THE SULIBAN.
I GOT SHOT IN THE LEG.
JUST BEFORE I PASSED OUT,
I REMEMBERED THINKING,
"THIS ISN'T
WHAT I SIGNED UP FOR.
"I SHOULD BE MAPPING
STAR CLUSTERS
OR MAKING FIRST CONTACT
WITH FRIENDLY SPECIES."
BUT WHEN THOSE SULIBAN
STARTED FIRING AT MY CREW,
I KNEW I DIDN'T HAVE ANY CHOICE
BUT TO FIGHT BACK.
I'M NOT ASHAMED TO ADMIT
I WAS NERVOUS--
I'M NERVOUS NOW--
BUT I KNOW WE CAN DO THIS.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: ARCHER.
Mayweather: The Klingon ship
just dropped out of warp,
Captain.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
LISTEN.
KLINGON: WHAT?
KOROK: THE PUMPS.
THEY'RE SILENT.
WHERE'S YOUR HOSPITALITY?
THIS IS NO WAY TO TREAT
YOUR FRIENDS!
[ WEAPON FIRES ]
SHOW YOURSELVES!
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ MAN TRILLING ]
KLINGON: HALT!
AGH!
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
THIS WILL COST YOU
MORE THAN DEUTERIUM!
[ SHOUTING IN KLINGON ]
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
ARCHER: AHEM.
T'POL: HEY!
T'POL: COME ON.
KLINGON: THERE.
KOROK: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'LL KILL US ALL.
THOSE WELLHEADS--
THEY'RE UNDER GREAT PRESSURE.
IF YOU IGNITE THEM,
YOU'LL INCINERATE
THE WHOLE TOWN.
KLINGON: THEY'RE MAKING FOOLS
OF US.
KOROK: THEY'RE HIDING
IN THE DIRT LIKE TARG.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
THEY'LL LEARN
TO SHOW US RESPECT.
WE'LL KILL ANOTHER FOUR...
PERHAPS THE BOY AS WELL.
CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE TOO FAR SOUTH.
AH. WE'VE GOT TO GET THEM TO
MOVE 50 METERS TO OUR LEFT.
EVERYBODY, THIS WAY.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
REED: A LITTLE FARTHER.
THIS IS GOOD.
A FEW MORE METERS.
[ CLANG ]
THIS SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
ARCHER: NOW.
ARCHER: THEY'RE ALL YOURS,
TESSIC.
KOROK!
I WOULDN'T DO THAT!
THERE'S TWO MORE WELLHEADS
BY YOUR FEET!
LEAVE HERE NOW
OR WE'LL IGNITE THEM!
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
YOU'LL LIVE TO REGRET THIS.
IF YOU'RE THINKING ABOUT COMING
BACK, I WOULDN'T ADVISE IT.
WE'LL BE READY.
WE'RE NOT AFRAID OF YOU ANYMORE.
WE CAN FIND DEUTERIUM ANYWHERE.
YOURS ISN'T FIT
FOR A GARBAGE SCOW.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
[ CHEERING ]
TUCKER: UNLESS YOU'RE PLANNING
TO JOIN STARFLEET,
I'M AFRAID YOU'LL HAVE
TO GIVE UP THAT CHAIR.
I WISH YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO LEAVE.
YEAH, THAT'S ONE OF THE TOUGH
THINGS ABOUT MY JOB--
SAYING GOODBYE TO PEOPLE
LIKE YOU AND YOUR FRIENDS.
OH. ALMOST FORGOT.
SCHEMATICS FOR ENTERPRISE.
YOU SAID YOU LIKE
TO LOOK AT STARSHIPS.
THIS ONE'LL KNOCK
YOUR SOCKS OFF.
THANKS.
DO YOU THINK YOU'LL COME BACK?
[ SIGHS ]
WHO KNOWS?
OUR ENGINES
NEED A LOT OF DEUTERIUM.
ARCHER: THERE MUST BE
OVER 1,000 LITERS HERE.
SECOND MAN: 2,000.
ARCHER: OUR DEAL WAS FOR 200.
TESSIC: OUR DEAL WAS
FOR POWER CELLS,
MEDICAL SUPPLIES,
AND REPAIR WORK.
YOU PROVIDED US
WITH MUCH MORE THAN THAT.
SECOND MAN: BESIDES, WE SEEM TO
HAVE A SURPLUS FOR THE MOMENT.
TESSIC: GIVE YOUR CREW
OUR THANKS.
ARCHER: HAVE A GOOD SEASON.