[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
SUBCOMMANDER?
YES?
VULCAN: DID I WAKE YOU?
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
WE'VE LOCATED MENOS.
WHERE?
VULCAN: LESS THAN THREE DAYS
FROM YOUR PRESENT LOCATION.
ARE YOU CERTAIN IT'S HIM?
YES.
MAN: ♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
Archer: Come in.
GOOD MORNING.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
TOAST?
T'POL: NO, THANK YOU.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
ADMIRAL FORREST
WILL BE CALLING YOU
THIS AFTERNOON, SIR.
OH, REALLY?
AND HOW WOULD YOU KNOW THAT?
I WAS CONTACTED BY THE VULCAN
HIGH COMMAND LAST NIGHT.
THEY'VE REQUESTED MY SERVICES
REGARDING A MATTER OF SECURITY.
AND THEY'VE ALREADY ASKED
ADMIRAL FORREST?
HE SHOULD BE CONTACTING YOU
THIS AFTERNOON.
A MATTER OF SECURITY?
THE ADMIRAL WILL INFORM YOU
THAT ENTERPRISE WILL BE ASKED
TO ALTER COURSE
TO THE PERNAIA SYSTEM,
WHERE I WILL NEED A SHUTTLEPOD
AND A PILOT
FOR THREE TO FIVE DAYS.
YOU DIDN'T ANSWER MY QUESTION.
WHAT KIND OF MATTER OF SECURITY?
A VULCAN SHIP WILL RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE SHUTTLEPOD
WHEN MY MISSION IS COMPLETED.
THEY'RE SENDING YOU
TO GET SOMEBODY --
SOMEBODY YOU'LL BE HANDING OVER
TO THE VULCANS.
WHY YOU?
ADMIRAL FORREST WILL BE
CONTACTING YOU THIS AFTERNOON.
THANKS FOR BEING
SO ENLIGHTENING.
DISMISSED.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
AS ANTICIPATED, I WAS CONTACTED
BY ADMIRAL FORREST,
WHO HAS ORDERED US
TO ACCOMMODATE
THE VULCANS' REQUEST.
ARCHER: DID YOU FIND
THE COORDINATES?
TRIP: PERNAIA PRIME.
YES, SIR.
ARCHER: SET A COURSE.
WHEN WE ARRIVE, YOU'LL BE
PILOTING THE SHUTTLEPOD.
TRAVIS: WHERE EXACTLY
WILL WE BE GOING?
ARCHER: SOMEWHERE IN
THE PERNAIA SYSTEM, NO DOUBT.
AS FAR AS THE EXACT LOCATION,
ADMIRAL FORREST
DOESN'T EVEN KNOW THAT.
SEEMS THE SUBCOMMANDER'S
ON A HIGHLY CLASSIFIED MISSION.
TRIP: IS THIS PERNAIA
PRIME INHABITED?
THE VULCAN DATABASE SAYS IT HAS
A METHANE-BASED ATMOSPHERE.
SO SHE'S GOING TO ANOTHER
PLANET IN THE SYSTEM.
[ LAUGHS ]
ARE WE SUPPOSED TO PLAY
SOME KIND OF GUESSING GAME?
ARCHER: NO, WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO WAIT AT PERNAIA PRIME
FOR T'POL AND TRAVIS
TO FINISH THEIR MISSION.
AND DO WHAT
IN THE MEANTIME?
REED: I COULD USE A FEW
DAYS TO RECALIBRATE
THE TORPEDO LAUNCHERS.
I COULD POLISH ALL THE HANDLES
AND RAILS IN ENGINEERING.
I GUESS I COULD PURGE
THE IMPULSE REACTORS.
IT'S ONLY FOR A FEW DAYS.
WE'VE GOT PLENTY
TO KEEP OURSELVES BUSY.
IS THERE ANYTHING SPECIFIC YOU
AND TRAVIS ARE GOING TO NEED?
COLD-WEATHER GEAR,
RESTRAINTS, AND PHASE PISTOLS.
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
IF THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
DOESN'T APPROVE
OF THE WATER-POLO MATCH
I'M WATCHING,
I'D BE HAPPY TO FIND ANOTHER.
T'POL: YOUR ORDERS TO BRING ME
TO PERNAIA CAME FROM STARFLEET,
NOT THE HIGH COMMAND.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
I HAVE A PERSONAL MATTER
I'D LIKE TO DISCUSS.
[ CHEERING STOPS ]
T'POL: BEFORE I JOINED
THE SCIENCE DIRECTORATE,
I WAS ASSIGNED
TO THE MINISTRY OF SECURITY.
I WAS TRAINED IN RECONNAISSANCE
AND RETRIEVAL.
MOVE OVER, PORTHOS.
LET THE LADY SIT DOWN.
SOUNDS LIKE THIS
IS GONNA BE GOOD.
COME ON, SIT DOWN.
HOW LONG AGO ARE
WE TALKING ABOUT?
I COMPLETED MY TRAINING
17 YEARS AGO.
GO AHEAD.
ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH A PLANET CALLED AGARON?
THEY'RE CLOSE ALLIES
WITH THE VULCANS, RIGHT?
NOT ALWAYS.
AGARON WAS
A VERY CORRUPT WORLD.
WHEN THEIR LEADERS
WERE FIRST TRYING
TO FORGE AN ALLIANCE
WITH VULCAN,
THEY ASKED FOR OUR ASSISTANCE.
THAT WAS NEARLY 30 YEARS AGO.
HUNDREDS OF OUR AGENTS
WERE SURGICALLY ALTERED
AND SENT TO INFILTRATE
THE MOST CRIMINAL FACTIONS
OF AGARON SOCIETY.
EVENTUALLY, THEY WERE
INSTRUMENTAL IN THE OVERTHROW
OF THOSE FACTIONS.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ME
YOU'RE ONE OF THOSE AGENTS.
I'M NOT THAT OLD, CAPTAIN.
AFTER THE ALLIANCE
WAS FORMALIZED,
THE VULCAN AGENTS WERE RECALLED.
THEY ALL RETURNED VOLUNTARILY --
ALL BUT 19.
I GUESS EVEN VULCANS
CAN FALL PREY TO TEMPTATION.
THE MINISTRY OF SECURITY
SENT A TEAM
OF NEWLY TRAINED OPERATIVES
TO RETRIEVE THEM.
I WAS ONLY ABLE
TO APPREHEND FIVE
OF THE SIX FUGITIVES
ASSIGNED TO ME.
SO, TOMORROW,
YOU GET TO PICK UP NUMBER SIX.
WHY COULDN'T SOMEONE ELSE DO IT?
WHY YOU?
THE MINISTRY CONSIDERS IT
A MATTER OF HONOR.
HOW VERY VULCAN.
SO...WHY HAVE YOU DECIDED
TO TELL ME ALL THIS?
I'D LIKE YOU TO COME WITH ME.
WHAT?
THE MAN I'M BEING SENT
TO APPREHEND
IS EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
IT WOULD BE WISE FOR ME
TO HAVE ASSISTANCE.
YOU SAID
THERE'S A VULCAN SHIP COMING.
I'M SURE THEY CAN PROVIDE
ALL THE ASSISTANCE YOU'LL NEED.
I'D PREFER IT
IF YOU'D COME WITH ME, CAPTAIN.
WHY?
I NEED TO BE
WITH SOMEONE I CAN TRUST.
IF YOU DON'T WISH TO HELP ME,
I UNDERSTAND.
GOOD NIGHT.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
THE MAN WE'RE GOING
TO APPREHEND?
MENOS.
SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
TRIP: IF YOU AGREED
TO GO WITH HER,
YOU MUST KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT WHAT SHE'S UP TO.
WE'LL BE BACK
IN THREE TO FIVE DAYS, TRIP.
IF THAT VULCAN SHIP
COMES SNOOPING AROUND,
THE LAST THING YOU WANT TO TELL
THEM IS THAT I'M WITH T'POL.
TRIP: WHY'S THAT?
WHY WOULD YOU BEING WITH HER
BE A PROBLEM TO THEM?
THREE TO FIVE DAYS, TRIP.
COME ON, CAPTAIN.
LAST NIGHT, YOU WERE
JUST AS FRUSTRATED AS I WAS
ABOUT HAVING TO SIT
ON YOUR HANDS
WHILE SHE GOES OFF AND DOES...
WHATEVER IT IS
SHE'S GOING OFF TO DO.
THIS ISN'T
JUST A CASE OF CURIOSITY.
BUT WHAT IF YOU GET HURT,
KIDNAPPED?
YOU PUT ME IN CHARGE
OF THIS SHIP.
YOU WON'T TELL ME
WHERE YOU'RE GOING?
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO BE
A GOOD TEMPORARY CAPTAIN
IF I DON'T KNOW
WHERE MY PEOPLE ARE?
TELL ME THAT.
ARCHER: SHE'S GOT SOME
UNFINISHED BUSINESS, TRIP.
I'M NOT SURE WHY,
BUT SHE NEEDS ME TO GO ALONG.
WE'LL BE OKAY.
TRIP: THERE ARE
A LOT OF DEFINITIONS
OF UNFINISHED BUSINESS.
COULD YOU BE
A LITTLE MORE SPECIFIC?
ARCHER: YOU'RE
IN CHARGE, COMMANDER.
HAVE YOU GIVEN TRAVIS
THE COORDINATES?
T'POL: YES.
HAVE FUN.
T'POL: BEFORE HE WAS
SENT TO AGARON,
THE DORSAL LOBES OF HIS EARS
WERE SURGICALLY ALTERED.
THE RIDGE ON HIS FOREHEAD
WAS ADDED SOMETIME AFTERWARD.
WHY DIDN'T HE WANT
TO COME HOME?
HE WAS ASSIGNED TO INFILTRATE
A CELL OF SMUGGLERS.
HE LEARNED THEIR CRAFT.
HE BECAME VERY PROFICIENT AT IT,
AMASSED A LARGE FORTUNE.
SMUGGLING WHAT?
SYNTHETIC BIO-TOXINS
USED TO MANUFACTURE
TRANSGENIC WEAPONS.
I SPENT THREE MONTHS
TRYING TO FIND HIM.
HE USED HIS WEALTH WISELY.
WHENEVER I'D GET CLOSE,
I'D FIND HE'D LEFT
A DAY OR TWO BEFORE.
YOU NEVER FOUND HIM?
ONLY ONCE, ON RISA.
THEY THOUGHT
THEY WERE INVULNERABLE.
THEY?
HE.
HE THOUGHT HE WAS
INVULNERABLE THERE,
THAT NO ONE WOULD
THINK TO LOOK FOR HIM
ON SUCH A PEACEFUL PLACE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I GOT VERY CLOSE --
20 METERS...MAYBE 10.
[ PANTING ]
T'POL?
I NEVER FOUND HIM AGAIN.
NO ONE DID...NOT UNTIL NOW.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ SCANNER BEEPING ]
HE'S HERE.
WHERE?
WITHIN 30 METERS.
IF HE SEES T'POL, HE MAY
TRY TO GET TO HIS SHIP.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
[ COINS CLATTERING ]
T'POL: HE SAW ME.
ARCHER: WHICH WAY?
T'POL: I'M NOT CERTAIN.
[ WHISTLES ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
COULDN'T AGREE MORE.
DON'T MOVE.
YOU HAVE NO JURISDICTION HERE.
FOLLOW ME.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
TRIP: COME IN.
GENTLEMEN, COME IN.
GLAD YOU COULD JOIN ME.
REED: WATER POLO?
VERY EXCITING SPORT.
YOU SHOULD LEARN MORE ABOUT IT.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
I HAD CHEF PREPARE
A SPECIAL LUNCH --
BANGERS AND MASH FOR YOU
AND, UH, DENOBULAN SAUSAGE
FOR THE DOCTOR.
PHLOX: VERY NICE.
REED: ARE YOU SURE THE CAPTAIN
WOULDN'T HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH YOU USING HIS DINING ROOM?
WELL, ACTING CAPTAIN,
CAPTAIN'S MESS --
I DON'T SEE A PROBLEM.
THANK YOU, CREWMAN.
ENJOY.
PHLOX: THANK YOU.
OH, I DETECTED A LYMPHATIC VIRUS
ONBOARD THIS MORNING.
MOST LIKELY IT SNEAKED IN
WITH ONE OF THE, UH,
DEUTERIUM CANISTERS.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY
INOCULATE THE CREW.
WHY DIDN'T THE BIO-SCANNERS
DETECT IT?
WELL, IT'S A VERY RELIABLE
DEVICE, BUT IT'S NOT PERFECT.
THE INOCULATION DOES HAVE
SOME, UM, SIDE EFFECTS.
WHAT KIND OF SIDE EFFECTS?
MM, HEADACHE, NAUSEA, DIARRHEA.
BUT THEY WOULD SUBSIDE
IN A DAY OR TWO.
DO I HAVE YOUR, UH, PERMISSION?
I'D HATE TO BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR GIVING THE CREW
THE -- THE RUNS.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD WAIT
TILL THE CAPTAIN GETS BACK.
I'M AFRAID THE VIRUS
WILL HAVE SPREAD BY THEN.
I REALLY NEED AN ANSWER TODAY.
[ SIGHS ]
WHY DON'T I GET
BACK TO YOU LATER, DOC?
NOT, UH, TOO MUCH LATER, HMM?
REED: WHILE WE'RE ON THE
SUBJECT OF APPROVALS,
I PROMISED CAPTAIN ARCHER
THAT I'D RECALIBRATE
THE TORPEDO LAUNCHERS.
I'LL NEED TO DIVERT COMPUTER
ACCESS FROM MAIN ENGINEERING.
THAT WOULD MEAN WE'D HAVE
TO POWER DOWN THE WARP CORE.
IT'LL ONLY BE FOR A DAY. WE'RE
NOT EXACTLY GOING ANYWHERE.
WELL, WE'RE ALSO NOT AT WAR.
I'M JUST NOT COMFORTABLE TAKING
THE ENGINES OFFLINE RIGHT NOW.
IS THAT THE CHIEF ENGINEER
TALKING OR THE ACTING CAPTAIN?
[ SIGHS ]
LET ME GET BACK TO YOU.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TUCKER.
Hoshi: We were just hailed
by the Vulcan ship Nyran, sir.
It's approaching the system
at high warp.
They're asking to speak
with Captain Archer.
TELL THEM, UM...
THE CAPTAIN'S INDISPOSED
AT THE MOMENT.
HE'LL GET BACK TO THEM
IN A LITTLE WHILE.
Hoshi: Yes, sir.
THE CAPTAIN SAID NOT TO TELL
THE VULCANS HE WENT WITH T'POL.
HE WAS, UM -- HE WAS
VERY EMPHATIC ABOUT THAT.
PHLOX: IT'S GOING
TO BE DIFFICULT
TO CONVINCE THEM
HE'S, UH, INDISPOSED
FOR THE NEXT FOUR DAYS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
GO AHEAD.
HOSHI: Captain Tavek says he has
a message from Admiral Forrest.
He seems very anxious
to speak with Captain Archer.
What shall I tell him?
I'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
[ SIGHS ]
YOUR WARRANT IS VALID,
BUT YOU WON'T BE ABLE
TO TAKE HIM --
NOT FOR AT LEAST FOUR HOURS.
WE'VE BEGUN THERMALIZING
THE LANDING DECK.
WE JUST NEED TO GET HIM
TO OUR SHIP.
THERE'S A HALF-CENTIMETER
OF XYLATHORIC ACID ON THAT DECK.
I WOULDN'T RECOMMEND IT,
NOT IF YOU VALUE
THOSE PRETTY FEET OF YOURS.
DO YOU HAVE SOMEWHERE
WE CAN PUT HIM UNTIL WE LEAVE?
DOES THIS LOOK
LIKE A PRISON TO YOU?
ANY ONE OF THESE PEOPLE
COULD BE WORKING WITH HIM.
T'POL: THE MINISTRY OF SECURITY
WAS VERY CLEAR ABOUT THAT.
HE WORKS ALONE.
I HAVEN'T ALWAYS.
[ PANTING ]
YOU'RE HUMAN.
AND YOU AS WELL.
THEY WANTED
TO REHABILITATE ME...
BRING ME HOME...
FLATTEN MY FOREHEAD
AND RE-POINT MY EARS.
THEY WANTED TO TEACH ME
TO FORGET THE LIFE
THEY HAD TAUGHT ME
SO CAREFULLY HOW TO LIVE.
THEY ASSUMED
I HAD BECOME CORRUPT
AND THAT,
LEFT TO MY OWN DEVICES,
I WOULD REMAIN CORRUPT.
THREE YEARS IN A VULCAN CLINIC.
REHABILITATION.
[ CHUCKLES ]
CAN YOU BLAME ME FOR RUNNING?
[ SIGHS ]
I'M NOT A THIEF.
I'M NOT A SMUGGLER.
I NEVER WAS.
I WORKED WITH SMUGGLERS.
I WORKED VERY CLOSE WITH THEM
FOR A LONG TIME.
IT'S WHAT I HAD BEEN TRAINED
TO DO.
DO YOU KNOW HOW I'VE SURVIVED
THE LAST 20 YEARS,
HOW I'VE FED MY FAMILY?
I HAUL
SPENT WARP-INJECTOR CASINGS --
NOT A VERY POPULAR OCCUPATION,
BUT A NECESSARY ONE.
A DOCTOR ON ANDORIA SAYS
THAT MY HEMOLYTIC-CELL COUNT
IS OVER 3,000.
YOU DON'T FIND TOO MANY OLD MEN
HAULING SPENT INJECTOR CASINGS.
UH, IN MY LEFT FRONT POCKET,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
I WOULDN'T. IT MAY BE A WEAPON.
IT'S A HOLOGRAM OF MY FAMILY.
IT WON'T HURT YOU.
THE INJECTOR CASINGS
ARE GOING TO TAKE ME AWAY
FROM THEM SOON ENOUGH.
I DON'T WANT TO DIE
IN A VULCAN PRISON.
THE INFORMATION
THAT I WAS GIVEN
SAYS THAT YOU BUY
HIGH-GRADE BIO-TOXINS
AND SELL THEM TO ANYONE
WHO WILL MEET YOUR PRICE.
IF ALL OF THE MINISTRY'S REPORTS
ABOUT ME WERE TRUE,
I COULD EASILY SHAPE-SHIFT AND
SLIP OUT OF THESE RESTRAINTS,
OR SPROUT WINGS
AND FLY TO MY SHIP.
ARCHER: WHY SHOULD SHE
BELIEVE A FUGITIVE
AND NOT HER OWN GOVERNMENT?
BECAUSE HER GOVERNMENT
SENT 109 AGENTS
TO AGARON 30 YEARS AGO,
AND THEY WANT
ALL 109 ACCOUNTED FOR,
RIGHT OR WRONG,
DEAD OR ALIVE.
IF YOU'RE INNOCENT,
I'M SURE YOU'LL BE GIVEN
A CHANCE TO DEFEND YOURSELF.
WELL, I'M GUILTY.
I'M GUILTY OF NOT RETURNING
WHEN I WAS TOLD TO.
I'M INNOCENT
OF SELLING BIO-TOXINS,
BUT I'M GUILTY
OF BEING A FUGITIVE.
BUT I DON'T DESERVE
TO GO TO PRISON,
AND I DON'T DESERVE TO BE SHOT.
WE'RE HERE TO TAKE YOU
TO VULCAN.
NO ONE'S GOING TO SHOOT YOU.
WHAT ABOUT HER?
[ PANTING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
YOU'RE A LIAR.
T'POL!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
T'POL?
HE'S NOT TELLING THE TRUTH.
WHERE THE HELL
ARE YOU GOING?
T'POL!
HE SAYS HE HAS A SHIP
FULL OF INJECTOR CASINGS.
ARCHER: BUT THE PLATFORM'S
COVERED WITH ACID.
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
JOSSEN!
[ SCREAMING ]
YOU'RE SURE?
THERE'S NO RECORD OF THEM
EVER HAVING SPOKEN,
BUT I CAN'T BE CERTAIN.
HAS HE EVER BEEN TO EARTH?
IF HE HAS, THE VULCAN DATABASE
DOESN'T MENTION IT.
WELL, I HOPE THEY HAVEN'T PUT
STARFLEET YEARBOOK PHOTOS
INTO THAT DATABASE.
OH, LET'S GET THIS OVER WITH.
CAPTAIN TAVEK, IS THERE
SOMETHING I CAN DO FOR YOU?
TAVEK: CAPTAIN ARCHER?
YES?
IS...THERE A PROBLEM?
YOU SEEM VERY YOUNG
FOR A STARFLEET CAPTAIN.
HEALTHY LIVING.
YOU HAVE A MESSAGE
FROM ADMIRAL FORREST?
I'M NOT CERTAIN
WHAT THIS MEANS,
BUT THE ADMIRAL ASKED ME
TO INFORM YOU THAT...
CAL BEAT STANFORD,
SEVEN TO THREE.
I'LL BE SURE TO TELL HIM.
TELL WHO?
UM, I'M AFRAID
IT'S CONFIDENTIAL.
THANK YOU
FOR RELAYING THE MESSAGE.
ARCHER OUT.
[ SIGHS ]
THAT WASN'T TOO SMART.
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN HURT.
WHAT DID YOU FIND?
T'POL:
SPENT INJECTOR CASINGS.
YOU'LL HAVE TO GO THROUGH DECON
WHEN WE GET BACK.
I WANT TO SPEAK TO MENOS ALONE.
WOULD YOU ALLOW ME TO DO THAT?
ARCHER: COME ON, TRAVIS.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN FIND
SOMETHING TO EAT.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SIGHS ]
WHO IS JOSSEN?
YOU DIDN'T FIND WHAT YOU
WERE LOOKING FOR, DID YOU?
WHO IS JOSSEN?
IF THIS IS YOUR IDEA OF HUMOR...
TELL ME WHO HE IS.
JOSSEN WAS NO DIFFERENT THAN ME.
HE DIDN'T WANT
TO BE REHABILITATED, EITHER.
[ GRUNTS ]
WHERE DID I MEET HIM?
MEET HIM?
ON RISA.
JOSSEN AND I WERE ON RISA
IN THE TROPICAL ZONE.
WE WERE INNOCENT
OF THE CRIMES
THE MINISTRY HAD ACCUSED US OF,
BUT WE WERE RUNNING
ALL THE SAME.
WHY DO YOU WANT ME TO TELL YOU
THINGS YOU ALREADY KNOW?
YOU'RE TELLING ME LIES.
NO. THE TRUTH.
I FOLLOWED YOU TO RISA,
NO ONE ELSE.
I BRIBED THE TELLARITE TRANSPORT
CAPTAIN WHO BROUGHT YOU THERE.
HE TOLD ME EXACTLY
WHERE TO FIND YOU.
I WASN'T LOOKING
FOR ANYONE ELSE.
THEN WHY ARE YOU
ASKING ME ABOUT JOSSEN?
HE NEVER HURT ANYONE.
HE DIDN'T DESERVE TO BE
HUNTED DOWN LIKE AN ANIMAL.
[ WEAPON FIRES ]
I KILLED HIM.
YES. AND HE DIDN'T
DESERVE TO BE KILLED.
HE WAS AN INNOCENT MAN,
JUST LIKE I AM.
[ GROANS ]
YOU REALLY DON'T REMEMBER.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
WHY DID YOU KILL HIM?
HE NEVER WOULD HAVE HURT YOU.
STOP TALKING.
YOU'RE A VULCAN.
YOU'RE TRAINED TO REPRESS
THE EMOTION OF KILLING,
NOT THE MEMORY OF THE ACT.
AAH!
I SAID STOP TALKING!
LOOK WHAT IT'S DONE TO YOU --
TAKING AN INNOCENT LIFE.
BRINGING ME BACK TO VULCAN
WILL BE NO DIFFERENT.
YOU'LL BE DESTROYING
ANOTHER LIFE.
HOW WILL THAT AFFECT YOU?
WILL YOU CONVENIENTLY FORGET
WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO DO TO ME?
WHERE'S MENOS?
ARCHER: GET BACK OVER THERE.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THERE WERE SEVEN.
SEVEN WHAT?
I WAS SENT TO BRING BACK
SEVEN FUGITIVES, NOT SIX.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
MENOS HAD A PARTNER
OR A FRIEND -- I'M NOT SURE.
HIS NAME WAS JOSSEN.
I FOLLOWED THEM BOTH TO RISA,
NOT JUST MENOS.
THE DAY I TOLD YOU I SAW MENOS
AND LOST HIM,
I SAW JOSSEN AS WELL.
THEY TRIED TO ESCAPE.
JOSSEN FELL TO THE GROUND.
HE BEGAN TO REACH
FOR HIS WEAPON.
BUT YOU FIRED FIRST?
I HAD FORGOTTEN ALL OF IT
UNTIL TODAY.
HOW?
HAVE YOU HEARD OF THE FULLARA?
NO.
IT'S AN OBSOLETE VULCAN RITUAL
WHERE THE MEMORY OF AN EVENT
IS REPRESSED
ALONG WITH THE EMOTIONS
ASSOCIATED WITH IT.
AND YOU HAD THIS...
FULLARA.
THIS FULLARA RITUAL
PERFORMED?
T'POL: WHEN I RETURNED TO
VULCAN, I WAS UNSETTLED.
I RESIGNED MY POSITION
WITH THE MINISTRY
AND SOUGHT GUIDANCE
AT THE SANCTUARY OF P'JEM.
FOR MONTHS, ONE OF THE ELDERS
WORKED WITH ME
TO CONTROL THE GUILT,
TO RESTRAIN THE DESPAIR
OF HAVING TAKEN A LIFE,
BUT THE FEELINGS REMAINED.
WHY WOULD YOU FEEL GUILTY
IF THIS JOSSEN
WAS ABOUT TO FIRE AT YOU?
I SUPPOSE I WAS NEVER CERTAIN
WHAT HIS INTENTIONS WERE.
THE ELDER HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO PERFORM THE RITUAL.
WHEN I LEFT THE SANCTUARY,
I DIDN'T REMEMBER ANYTHING
ABOUT JOSSEN OR THE FULLARA.
WHEN DID IT START COMING BACK?
WHEN THE FIRST CALL CAME IN
ABOUT THIS NEW MISSION.
MAYBE THAT'S WHY
I WANTED YOU WITH ME.
WHAT IF JOSSEN
WASN'T A SMUGGLER?
WHAT IF HE WAS INNOCENT?
THEN IT WOULDN'T HAVE MATTERED
WHETHER HE INTENDED TO USE
THAT WEAPON OR NOT.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
WHAT'S MENOS BEEN TELLING YOU?
MENOS' SHIP WAS FILLED WITH
INJECTOR CASINGS, NOTHING ELSE.
HE HAS A FAMILY.
OUR SCANS SHOULD BE ABLE
TO CONFIRM IF HE'S DYING
OF RADIATION POISONING.
WHAT'S HE BEEN TELLING YOU?
[ CRASH, INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
HE KICKED OVER THE TABLE!
AND YOU CLAIM YOU'RE
A PEACEFUL MAN.
IRONIC, ISN'T IT?
BURNING TO DEATH
ON A FROZEN MOON?
BUT I'D RATHER DIE HERE
THAN BE BROUGHT BACK
AND PUNISHED FOR CRIMES
I NEVER COMMITTED.
T'POL!
REFASTEN THEM.
OH!
T'POL: WHERE'S MENOS?
ARCHER: TRAVIS!
COME ON.
WHERE'S HIS SHIP?
YOUR MISSION IS
TO RETURN HIM TO VULCAN,
NOT DETERMINE
WHETHER HE'S GUILTY OR INNOCENT.
WHERE'S HIS SHIP?
HE'S NOT ABOARD.
LET'S BE SURE.
WE'LL ALL NEED TO GO
THROUGH DECON NOW.
HE'S NOT HERE.
WAS THAT THE ONLY WAY IN?
GO BACK TO THE COCKPIT, TRAVIS.
AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: GET LIFE SUPPORT
FIRED UP IF YOU CAN.
IT'S PRETTY COLD.
HE SHOULD'VE GOTTEN HERE
BEFORE US.
THIS SHIP SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
T'POL: WHY RISK USING
HIS OWN VESSEL?
HE'D KNOW WE'D FOLLOW HIM.
SO HE COULD'VE LEFT WITH
ANY ONE OF THOSE OTHER SHIPS.
ANY ONE OF THEM.
YOU SEEM OKAY WITH THAT.
WHEN WE RETURN TO ENTERPRISE,
I'LL INFORM THE VULCAN SHIP
THAT MENOS ESCAPED.
IF THE HIGH COMMAND WISHES,
THEY CAN QUESTION AS MANY
OF THE VESSELS THAT LEFT HERE
AS THEY CAN FIND.
YOU'RE GIVING UP A LOT EASIER
THAN I WOULD'VE GUESSED.
HE'S OBVIOUSLY GONE.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
HE GOT TO YOU, DIDN'T HE?
YOU'RE BEGINNING
TO DOUBT YOURSELF.
HE FIGURED IF HE COULD GET YOU
TO QUESTION
WHAT YOU DID 17 YEARS AGO,
YOU'D BEGIN TO QUESTION
WHAT YOU'RE DOING RIGHT NOW.
I MAY HAVE KILLED
AN INNOCENT MAN 17 YEARS AGO.
DID JOSSEN REACH
FOR HIS WEAPON OR NOT?
T'POL: I DON'T KNOW.
ARCHER: IS THAT
WHAT YOU REMEMBER
OR WHAT MENOS WANTS YOU
TO REMEMBER?
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
THERE'S A BIG
DIFFERENCE.
HE'S PLAYING ON YOUR GUILT.
DON'T YOU SEE THAT?
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
I WENT TO P'JEM.
THEY PERFORMED THE RITUAL --
DON'T GIVE ME THAT!
YOUR EMOTIONAL IMMUNE SYSTEM
STARTED TO COLLAPSE AGAIN
THE MINUTE YOU REMEMBERED
WHAT HAPPENED THAT DAY ON RISA.
TRAVIS: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WHAT IS IT, TRAVIS?
THERE'S SOMETHING FUNNY
UP HERE, SIR.
YOU THINK YOU COULD TAKE A LOOK?
ARCHER: WHAT'S UP?
AFTER I GOT THE BOARD RUNNING,
I BROUGHT LIFE SUPPORT UP
TO LEVEL THREE.
AS SOON AS I GOT
MORE LIGHT IN HERE,
I NOTICED SOME CONDENSATION
ON THIS SUB-PANEL.
ARCHER: THERE'S A HELL OF
A LOT OF ENERGY FLOWING
THROUGH THOSE CIRCUITS.
ANY IDEA WHAT THEY ARE?
OUR SCANNER SHOWED
EVERYTHING POWERED DOWN.
WELL, OBVIOUSLY,
SOMETHING'S POWERED UP.
THERE'S ONE WAY TO
FIND OUT WHAT IT IS.
I'M A VERY PATIENT MAN, T'POL.
I WAS SIMPLY WAITING
FOR YOU TO LEAVE,
BUT YOUR CAPTAIN'S CURIOSITY
HAS PUT AN END TO THAT.
WOULD YOU PLEASE
LOWER YOUR WEAPON?
ARCHER: THERE'S SOME KIND
OF ENERGY FIELD RUNNING...
I DON'T WANT TO HARM T'POL,
CAPTAIN, BUT I WILL.
THOSE ARE VIOLENT WORDS
FOR A PEACEFUL MAN.
AT THE MOMENT, I'M A MAN
WHO NEEDS TO SURVIVE.
THERE'S A LOCKER
RIGHT NEXT TO YOU.
I WANT YOU TO BOTH
PUT YOUR WEAPONS DOWN
AND THEN WALK INTO IT.
YOU WON'T BE HURT.
WHAT ABOUT HER?
MENOS: T'POL IS MY GUARANTEE
THAT THE TWO OF YOU WILL WALK
QUICKLY AND QUIETLY
INTO THE LOCKER.
PLEASE.
THE LOCKING CODE IS 1661.
THERE'S A VERY SPECIFIC TONE
WHEN IT'S ENTERED PROPERLY.
[ GRUNTS ]
ARCHER: YOU OKAY?
T'POL: YES.
WE DON'T DO QUICKLY AND QUIETLY
VERY WELL,
BUT WE ARE GOOD
AT ARITHMETIC.
SEEMS THERE ARE THREE OF US
AND ONLY ONE OF YOU.
STOP! PLEASE!
I DON'T TRUST THIS GUY, TRAVIS.
FIND SOMETHING TO
TIE HIM UP WITH.
AYE, SIR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GET UP!
STOP!
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO SHOOT ME, T'POL.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO KILL
ANOTHER INNOCENT MAN.
MENOS: THIS IS NONE
OF YOUR CONCERN, CAPTAIN.
YOU KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED ON RISA.
CAPTAIN?
WHY DID YOU WANT ME HERE?
BECAUSE I TRUST YOU.
THEN TRUST ME.
YOU WERE SENT TO APPREHEND HIM,
NOT TO JUDGE HIM.
[ GRUNTS ]
HE'S NOT GONNA GET
OUT OF THAT TOO QUICKLY.
TRAVIS: I THINK I KNOW
WHY HE WAS SO NERVOUS
ABOUT US FIRING AT HIM
WHILE HE WAS OVER HERE.
LOOK AT THIS.
BIO-TOXINS.
IF ONE OF OUR WEAPONS
HAD STRUCK THIS...
I GUESS HE WAS HAULING MORE THAN
INJECTOR CASINGS, AFTER ALL.
I GUESS HE WAS.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE VULCAN SHIP NYRAN
WAS WAITING
AT THE PREARRANGED COORDINATES.
AFTER TRANSFERRING MENOS
TO THEIR CUSTODY,
WE'VE RETURNED TO ENTERPRISE.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS, TRIP?
Trip: Everything's ready to go,
Captain. Welcome back.
THANKS.
WE'LL BE GOING TO WARP 3.
Trip: You got it.
UM...
NOW THAT YOUR SECRET MISSION
IS OVER,
YOU THINK YOU COULD GIVE
YOUR CHIEF ENGINEER
A LITTLE HINT
ABOUT WHAT YOU WERE UP TO?
DID I SAY WARP 3?
I MEANT WARP 4, COMMANDER.
NOT EVEN A HINT?
WARP 4. AYE, CAPTAIN.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
SUBCOMMANDER.
AM I ABOUT TO GET ANOTHER CALL
FROM ADMIRAL FORREST?
NO, SIR.
SORRY.
DEALING WITH THESE MEMORIES --
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
EASY FOR YOU, IS IT?
NO, IT'S NOT.
IF YOU FEEL YOU NEED
A LEAVE OF ABSENCE --
THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY.
I WAS MUCH YOUNGER THEN.
YOU'VE ALSO SPENT A LOT OF TIME
AROUND HUMANS LATELY.
YOU DO HAVE A WAY OF PUTTING
QUESTIONABLE ACTIONS BEHIND YOU.
WHEN YOU DON'T HAVE THE ABILITY
TO REPRESS EMOTIONS,
YOU LEARN TO DEAL WITH THEM
AND MOVE ON.
WAS THERE SOMETHING ELSE?
IF YOU EVER NEED
SOMEONE YOU CAN TRUST...
I WON'T FORGET.