I NEED TO SPEND
MORE TIME IN THE GYM.
IF I'D KNOWN THERE WERE
GONNA BE SO MANY HILLS,
I WOULD HAVE PICKED
A DIFFERENT CITY TO EXPLORE.
IT WAS WORTH EVERY STEP, SIR.
THE ARCHITECTURE ALONE.
I COULD HAVE SPENT
ALL DAY IN THAT TEMPLE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
REED: WITH YOUR
PERMISSION, CAPTAIN,
I'D LIKE TO WRITE
THE REPORT TO STARFLEET.
IT WAS MY FIRST VISIT
TO A PRE-WARP CULTURE.
SEEMS ONLY FITTING.
I DON'T SUPPOSE IT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE TACTICAL SITUATION
DOWN THERE.
[ SIGHS ]
AM I THAT OBVIOUS?
[ LAUGHTER ]
I CAN'T THINK OF A BETTER MAN
FOR THE JOB.
WELCOME HOME.
ANY UNEXPECTED GUESTS?
NOT A SINGLE PARASITE,
SPORE, OR VIRUS.
I TAKE IT YOUR EXPEDITION
WAS PRODUCTIVE?
VERY.
YOU'RE DONE HERE.
YOU KNOW, AS INTERESTING
AS THAT WAS,
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD TO GET HOME.
THE SPEAKER AT
THE POLITICAL RALLY --
WHAT WAS HIS NAME --
CHANCELLOR KULTREY?
KULTAREY.
[ CHUCKLES ] YOU COULD WRITE
A BOOK ABOUT HIM ALONE.
HIS SPEECH REMINDED ME
OF WINSTON CHURCHILL
BEFORE THE SECOND WORLD WAR.
SOMETHING WRONG?
MALCOLM?
MY COMMUNICATOR.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
IT'S GONE.
MAN: ♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
IT'S NOT IN DECON.
REED: ANY LUCK?
ARCHER: NOT YET.
WHAT ABOUT THE LAUNCH BAY CREW?
COULD THEY HAVE FOUND IT WHILE
THEY WERE SECURING THE POD?
I'VE ALREADY SPOKEN TO THEM.
I DID EVERYTHING
BUT TEAR UP THE FLOOR PLATING.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU REMEMBER HAVING IT?
I CONTACTED T'POL TO LET HER
KNOW WE'D ENTERED THE CITY.
AFTER THAT,
DID YOU HAVE ANY REASON
TO TAKE IT OUT
OF YOUR POCKET?
NO.
ARCHER: ARE YOU SURE?
I'D REMEMBER.
EITHER I DROPPED IT
OR SOMEONE PICKED MY POCKET.
WE COVERED A LOT OF GROUND.
IT COULD BE ANYWHERE.
I THINK I CAN NARROW DOWN
THE SEARCH, CAPTAIN.
AN INVERSE CARRIER WAVE SHOULD
AMPLIFY ITS POWER SIGNATURE.
WITH ANY LUCK, I'LL BE
ABLE TO ISOLATE IT.
I'M GETTING SOMETHING.
I'VE GOT IT DOWN
TO TWO SQUARE KILOMETERS.
ARCHER: CAN YOU DO
A LITTLE BETTER?
I'LL TRY.
DIDN'T YOU SAY SOMETHING
ABOUT A WAR BREWING DOWN THERE?
WE SAW A LOT OF PROPAGANDA,
BUT FROM WHAT WE COULD TELL,
NOBODY'S STARTED FIGHTING.
T'POL: IT'S CRUCIAL
WE RETRIEVE THE TECHNOLOGY.
WE CAN'T RISK CONTAMINATING
A PRE-WARP CULTURE.
I'VE ISOLATED THE SIGNAL
TO WITHIN THREE CITY BLOCKS.
HOSHI: THAT'S THE BEST
I CAN DO, SIR.
THIS L-SHAPED STRUCTURE --
ISN'T THAT THE FOUNTAIN,
THE ONE WITH THE STATUES?
THE TAVERN WAS DIRECTLY
ACROSS THE STREET HERE.
THE COMMUNICATOR COULD HAVE
SLIPPED OUT OF MY POCKET
WHEN WE SAT DOWN.
IT'S A GOOD PLACE TO START.
YOU'VE GOT THE BRIDGE.
TELL DR. PHLOX
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
HIS COSMETIC SERVICES AGAIN.
TRIP: YOU COULD USE ANOTHER SET
OF EYES DOWN THERE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: I APPRECIATE
THE OFFER, TRIP,
BUT THE FEWER SET OF EYES,
THE BETTER.
I'M A REGULAR BLOODHOUND.
NEXT TIME.
WE'LL BE IN RANGE OF THEIR
SURVEILLANCE TOWERS
IN LESS THAN TWO MINUTES.
THE HULL PLATING'S
ALREADY BEEN POLARIZED.
YOUR FEET READY
FOR ANOTHER HIKE?
IT'S NOT A PROBLEM, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
MY CARELESSNESS WAS INEXCUSABLE.
I'M PREPARED
FOR WHATEVER REPRIMAND
YOU FEEL IS APPROPRIATE.
HOW ABOUT 30 YEARS IN THE BRIG?
OR MAYBE A GOOD FLOGGING?
REED: SIR --
ARCHER: IT WAS
AN ACCIDENT, MALCOLM.
IT COULD HAVE HAPPENED
TO ANY OF US.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THREE MILITARY AIRCRAFT
72 KILOMETERS OFF STARBOARD.
I SUGGEST YOU INCREASE
OUR DESCENT VECTOR.
THAT SHOULD KEEP US WELL BELOW
THEIR VISUAL THRESHOLD.
THIS WAS THE TABLE?
POSITIVE.
TRY YOUR SCANNER.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
WELCOME BACK.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
CAN YOU GIVE US
A FEW MINUTES?
OF COURSE.
WHERE'S YOUR FRIEND --
THE YOUNG WOMAN?
YOU HAVE A GOOD MEMORY.
SHE WAS DIFFICULT TO FORGET.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'LL PASS ALONG THE COMPLIMENT.
DO YOU LIVE HERE?
NO, JUST VISITING.
WE RECEIVED A SHIPMENT
OF ALLAKAS MALT THIS AFTERNOON.
SOUNDS GOOD.
REED: I'VE GOT IT.
ARCHER: WHERE?
IT'S IN A ROOM...
OFF THAT CORRIDOR.
WERE YOU IN THERE?
NO.
THERE ARE TWO PEOPLE INSIDE.
BETTER WAIT TILL THEY COME OUT.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
DOES THIS BELONG TO YOU?
MAN: WHAT IS IT?
ARCHER: I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT KIND OF WEAPON IS THIS?
WHERE'S GENERAL GOSIS?
ON THE EASTERN PERIMETER.
SEND A LEVEL-FOUR COMMUNIQUE
AND TELL HIM I THINK WE FOUND
A PAIR OF ENEMY SPIES.
TAKE THEM TO THE COMPLEX
AND PUT YOUR MEN ON ALERT.
YOU WON'T BE SEEING YOUR FRIENDS
IN THE ALLIANCE FOR A LONG TIME.
I'M TELLING YOU,
SOMETHING'S GONE WRONG.
WE SHOULD HAIL THEM.
IF THEY'RE IN A PUBLIC PLACE,
THE COMMUNICATOR
WOULD DRAW ATTENTION.
WE'LL HAVE TO TAKE THAT RISK.
T'POL TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
THE COM LINE'S OPEN.
CAPTAIN, PLEASE RESPOND.
CLOSE THE CHANNEL.
DID YOU GET A FIX ON THE SIGNAL?
SOMEWHERE IN THIS DISTRICT.
TRIP: THAT'S MORE THAN
30 KILOMETERS FROM THE TAVERN.
WHERE'S THE SHUTTLEPOD?
IT HASN'T MOVED.
THEY COULDN'T HAVE TRAVELED
THAT FAR ON FOOT, NOT THAT FAST.
MAYBE THEY TOOK A TRAIN
OR A CAR.
IF THERE WAS A CHANGE OF PLAN,
THEY WOULD'VE TOLD US.
TRY TO ISOLATE THEIR BIO-SIGNS.
I WANT TO KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE THEY ARE.
THERE ARE NEARLY 100,000 PEOPLE
IN THAT PART OF THE CITY.
WE'D HAVE MORE LUCK
IF WE MOVED INTO A LOWER ORBIT.
ANY CLOSER
AND WE'D BE DETECTED.
DO YOUR BEST.
[ GROANS ]
STILL BOTHERING YOU?
I DIDN'T HAVE TIME TO VISIT
THE DOCTOR.
REED: I WONDER IF THE GUARD
WOULD BRING US SOME EPSOM SALTS,
UH, IF I ASKED POLITELY.
WOULDN'T COUNT ON IT.
WE CAME DOWN TO RETRIEVE
MY COMMUNICATOR.
NOW WE'VE LOST TWO OF THEM,
NOT TO MENTION MY PHASE PISTOL
AND A PAIR OF SCANNERS.
LET'S JUST HOPE THEY DON'T FIND
THE SHUTTLEPOD.
IF THEY REALLY THINK
WE ARE SPYING FOR THIS ALLIANCE,
PERHAPS WE SHOULD CONSIDER
TELLING THEM THE TRUTH.
I'M NOT SURE ANYONE
WOULD BELIEVE US.
WELL, IT COULDN'T HURT TO TRY.
VISITORS FROM ANOTHER WORLD?
THERE'S NO WAY TO KNOW
HOW THEY'D REACT.
[ DOOR OPENS,
FOOTSTEPS APPROACH ]
THE LESS WE SAY, THE BETTER.
UNDERSTOOD.
FOLLOW ME.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
MAN: WHICH OF YOU
IS THE CAPTAIN?
SOMETHING UNEXPECTED HAPPENED
WHEN I WAS EXAMINING
THIS TRANSMITTER.
IT BEGAN TO MAKE A SOUND,
SO I OPENED IT.
SOMEONE CALLING HERSELF T'POL
SEEMED VERY CONCERNED
ABOUT HER CAPTAIN'S WELL-BEING.
WHICH ONE OF YOU WAS
SHE TRYING TO CONTACT?
I'M THE CAPTAIN.
THE ALLIANCE MUST BE
GROWING DESPERATE
IF THEY'RE RECRUITING
MILITARY OFFICERS AS SPIES.
WE'RE NOT PART OF THE MILITARY.
OH, I SUPPOSE YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN
OF A PLEASURE BOAT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THIS TRANSCEIVER --
WHAT'S ITS FREQUENCY, ITS RANGE?
I DON'T KNOW.
THIS APPEARS TO BE
A COMPUTING INSTRUMENT.
TELL ME, HOW DOES IT WORK?
[ GROANS ]
MY SUPERIORS EXPECT ANSWERS.
AS AN OFFICER, I'M SURE
YOU CAN APPRECIATE THAT.
I HAVE NO DESIRE TO HARM YOU,
BUT I NEED YOU TO COOPERATE.
I'M SORRY. I CAN'T HELP YOU.
I TRUST YOU ENJOYED
THE RALLY THIS MORNING.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S CURIOUS, THE TWO OF YOU
VISITING THIS CITY
THE SAME DAY
AS CHANCELLOR KULTAREY.
DID YOU COME HERE TO OBSERVE
HIS SECURITY ARRANGEMENTS
OR PERHAPS ASSASSINATE HIM?
WE'RE AWARE OF YOUR ANCESTRAL
CLAIMS AGAINST OUR CITY.
IT MUST MAKE A TEMPTING TARGET.
WE'RE VISITORS, NOT SPIES.
THIS T'POL WHO TRIED
TO CONTACT YOU, WHERE IS SHE?
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
THEY'VE BEEN SURGICALLY ALTERED.
GENERAL.
HIS BLOOD -- IT'S RED.
TAKE THEM TO TEMEC.
HAVE HIM PERFORM
A FULL EXAMINATION.
THEY'RE HERE,
INSIDE THIS COMPOUND.
GUARD TOWERS, GUN EMPLACEMENTS.
IT'S NOT A HOTEL.
WELL, WE COULD TAKE
SHUTTLEPOD 2, SET IT DOWN HERE.
THEY'RE BEING HELD
LESS THAN 30 METERS AWAY.
WE'D BE BACK IN ORBIT BEFORE
ANYONE KNEW THEY WERE GONE.
IF YOU WERE CAPTURED,
YOU'D BE GIVING THE INHABITANTS
MORE TECHNOLOGY.
IT WOULD UNDOUBTEDLY AFFECT
THE EVOLUTION OF THEIR SOCIETY.
WHAT IF THEY DIDN'T
SEE US COMING?
TRIP: WE'VE STILL GOT
THAT SULIBAN CELL SHIP,
THE ONE WE USED TO RESCUE
KLAANG FROM THE HELIX.
I'VE BEEN WORKING ON IT
IN MY FREE TIME.
I'M PRETTY CLOSE
TO FIGURING OUT HOW IT WORKS.
IF I CAN BRING THE CLOAK ONLINE,
WE CAN GET PAST THEIR DEFENSES,
GRAB OUR PEOPLE,
AND NO ONE WILL SEE A THING.
WORK QUICKLY.
I COULD USE A HAND.
AYE, SIR.
I SUGGEST WE MONITOR
THE COMMUNIQUES
COMING FROM THE COMPOUND.
THEY MAY TELL US
WHAT'S HAPPENING
TO THE CAPTAIN AND MR. REED.
HOSHI: RIGHT AWAY.
TRIP: I DON'T GET IT.
THE POWER CONVERTER'S ENGAGED.
JUICE IS DEFINITELY FLOWING
THROUGH THESE RELAYS.
SO WHY CAN WE
STILL SEE THE SHIP?
MAYBE THIS PANEL
ISN'T THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
I'VE IDENTIFIED
EVERY OTHER COMPONENT.
THAT'S GOT TO BE IT.
RUN THE POWER-UP SEQUENCE AGAIN.
THIS WOULD BE A LOT EASIER
IF THERE WAS A BUTTON
MARKED "CLOAK."
HOLD ON A MINUTE, TRAVIS.
AAH!
TRIP: [ GROANING ]
TRAVIS: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
JUST GOT THE WIND
KNOCKED OUT OF ME A BIT.
MAYBE A LITTLE MORE THAN THAT.
HMM. IS THERE ANY PAIN?
IT TINGLES A LITTLE.
YEAH? CAN YOU, UH,
MOVE YOUR FINGERS?
HOW'S THAT?
YOU TELL ME.
THEY FEEL ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S YOUR SCANNER SAY?
VERY LITTLE, I'M AFRAID.
QUANTUM PHYSICS IS
HARDLY MY SPECIALTY,
BUT, UH, I'D GUESS THAT YOU
RECEIVED AN INTENSE DOSE
OF WHATEVER PARTICLE RADIATION
THAT SHIP USES
TO CONCEAL ITSELF.
ARE YOU SAYING
I'M PERMANENTLY CLOAKED?
IT'S DIFFICULT TO DETERMINE,
BUT, UH, I SUSPECT
YOUR APPENDAGE
WILL EVENTUALLY REMATERIALIZE
ON ITS OWN.
EVENTUALLY?
COME BACK IN AN HOUR.
I'LL CHECK ON YOUR PROGRESS.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO
IN THE MEANTIME?
I CAN'T WORK LIKE THIS.
[ SIGHS ]
I'D ALSO RECOMMEND
A FRESH UNIFORM.
THANKS.
SHALL WE TRY THIS?
SOME KIND OF COHERENT
ENERGY PULSE.
I THOUGHT THIS TECHNOLOGY
WAS ONLY THEORETICAL.
OUR ALLIANCE FRIENDS SEEM TO
HAVE TURNED THEORY INTO REALITY.
MAY I?
THERE APPEARS TO BE
ANOTHER SETTING.
IF THE ALLIANCE HAS EQUIPPED
ITS TROOPS WITH THESE WEAPONS...
MAKE SURE THE DEVICES ARE KEPT
UNDER GUARD AT ALL TIMES.
USE MEN YOU CAN TRUST.
WHAT DID YOU FIND?
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
HOW IS THIS POSSIBLE?
THERE'S ONLY ONE EXPLANATION.
OUR PRISONERS BELONG
TO ANOTHER SPECIES.
DR. TEMEC TELLS ME
YOUR DEFORMITIES
ARE NOT THE WORK OF A SURGEON.
HE FOUND NO OBVIOUS INCISIONS
OR SCAR TISSUE.
YOU'RE EVEN MORE ABNORMAL
ON THE INSIDE --
A REDUNDANT RENAL ORGAN,
AND YOU'RE MISSING
FOUR THORACIC VERTEBRAE.
TEMEC CAN'T EVEN BEGIN
TO EXPLAIN THIS MASS.
AS FOR YOUR RED BLOOD, THE
DOCTOR TELLS ME YOUR HEMOGLOBIN
IS BASED ON IRON,
A TOXIC ELEMENT.
HE CONDUCTED THE TEST
FOUR TIMES TO BE CERTAIN.
HE HAS A THEORY
ABOUT WHERE YOU CAME FROM.
I FOUND IT DIFFICULT TO BELIEVE
UNTIL I SAW THIS.
ONE OF OUR SURVEILLANCE AIRCRAFT
TOOK THIS IMAGE
EARLY THIS MORNING.
THE PILOT SAID THE OBJECT WAS
TRAVELING AT VERY HIGH SPEED.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN?
MAN: NONE OF THE OTHER PLANETS
IN OUR SYSTEM ARE CAPABLE
OF SUPPORTING LIFE.
WHERE DO YOU COME FROM?
OUR SCIENTISTS TELL ME
IT'S UNLIKELY
THAT A CRAFT OF THIS SIZE
COULD HAVE TRAVELED
FROM ANOTHER STAR SYSTEM.
THEY SUSPECT A LARGER SHIP
MUST BE SOMEWHERE NEARBY --
PERHAPS ORBITING OUR PLANET.
TELL ME YOUR ORDERS!
HAVE YOU MADE CONTACT
WITH THE ALLIANCE?
[ GRUNTS ]
ANSWER ME!
OUR INTELLIGENCE REPORTS
UNDERESTIMATE YOU, GENERAL.
[ CHUCKLES ]
ALIEN CREATURES.
YOU'RE EVEN MORE DELUSIONAL
THAN WE THOUGHT.
THIS ISN'T A SPACE SHIP.
IT'S SUBORBITAL --
A HIGHLY EXPERIMENTAL AIRCRAFT.
WE'VE BEEN OBSERVING
YOUR TERRITORY FOR MONTHS.
HOW DID YOU EVADE
OUR SURVEILLANCE TOWERS?
IT'S MADE
FROM A COMPOSITE ALLOY...
INVISIBLE TO ANY
OF YOUR TRACKING SYSTEMS.
AND YOUR BIOLOGICAL ANOMALIES?
WE'VE BEEN GENETICALLY ENHANCED.
WHAT KIND OF ENHANCEMENTS?
OUR IMMUNE SYSTEMS ARE RESISTANT
TO CHEMICAL
AND BIOLOGICAL WEAPONS,
AND OUR INTERNAL ORGANS
HAVE BEEN MODIFIED
TO INCREASE
CELLULAR REGENERATION BY 30%.
THAT WAY OUR WOUNDS
CAN HEAL MORE QUICKLY.
CREATE THE PERFECT SOLDIER.
HOW MANY OF YOU ARE THERE?
WE'RE PROTOTYPES. THE ONLY ONES.
AND YOUR DEVICES --
ARE THEY PROTOTYPES AS WELL?
ALL OF THEM.
TAKE THEM BACK.
DO YOU BELIEVE THEM?
IT'S A PLAUSIBLE EXPLANATION.
THE ALLIANCE COULD HAVE
THOUSANDS OF SOLDIERS
WITH THESE MUTATIONS.
WE NEED TO VERIFY
WHAT THEY'VE TOLD US.
I RAN EVERY IMAGINABLE TEST.
IF...
I WERE TO EXTRACT THE ORGANS...
I COULD STUDY THEM
IN MORE DETAIL.
YOU'LL BE IN CHARGE
OF THE EXECUTION.
I'LL INFORM THE PRISONERS.
SUBCOMMANDER,
ANOTHER COMMUNIQUE.
IT'S FROM A GENERAL GOSIS
TO THE CHANCELLOR.
HE SAID THEY'VE CAPTURED
TWO ENEMY SPIES.
THEY'RE GONNA HANG THEM.
RECONNECT
THE DIFFRACTION RELAYS,
AND WE'LL GIVE IT ANOTHER SHOT.
TRAVIS: ANY CHANGE?
STILL MISSING IN ACTION.
HAVING A CLOAKED HAND
COULD HAVE ITS ADVANTAGES.
BE USEFUL IN A POKER MATCH.
I COULD PROBABLY BECOME
A WORLD-CLASS MAGICIAN.
TRAVIS: IT MIGHT BE HELPFUL ON
MOVIE NIGHT IF YOU BRING A DATE.
IN CASE YOU WANT TO STEAL
SOME POPCORN.
LET'S TRY IT AGAIN.
GO AHEAD.
IS IT WORKING?
NOT EXACTLY. SHUT HER DOWN.
THE CLOAKING GENERATOR'S
RUNNING AT 110%.
IT'S STILL NOT ENOUGH.
LET'S ROUTE MORE POWER
FROM THE WARP RELAYS.
MAYBE THAT'LL DO THE TRICK.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
HOW SOON CAN YOU LAUNCH?
WE'RE STILL RECONFIGURING
THE POWER MATRIX,
BUT I'M PRETTY CONFIDENT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TIME.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE EXECUTED
IN LESS THAN TWO HOURS.
WE'LL GET IT WORKING ON
OUR WAY DOWN IF WE HAVE TO.
LOOK, INVISIBLE OR NOT,
THIS CELL SHIP COULD
TAKE MORE OF A BEATING
THAN OUR SHUTTLEPOD.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO FIND OUT.
PREPARE IT FOR LAUNCH.
ARCHER: AN UPSET STOMACH?
DO YOU REALLY THINK
HE'D FALL FOR THAT?
REED: WELL, IT MAY BE AN OLD
TRICK WHERE WE COME FROM,
BUT MAYBE THEY HAVEN'T
HEARD OF IT HERE.
ARCHER: EVEN IF WE
GOT OUT OF THE COMPOUND,
WE'D NEVER MAKE IT
TO THE SHUTTLE --
NOT LOOKING LIKE THIS.
GENETIC ENHANCEMENTS --
VERY CREATIVE, MALCOLM.
REED: THANKS.
IMPROVISATION
ISN'T MY STRONG SUIT.
ARCHER: YOU MADE US SOUND
LIKE THE SULIBAN.
REED: WHAT DO YOU SUPPOSE
ENTERPRISE WILL DO...
AFTER WE'RE...
IF I KNOW T'POL...
SHE WON'T WANT TO LEAVE
ANY CONTAMINATION BEHIND.
IT MAY TAKE SOME TIME,
BUT SHE'LL FIND A WAY
TO GET EVERYTHING BACK...
INCLUDING OUR...
REMAINS.
[ SIGHS ]
IT'S IRONIC...
GIVING OUR LIVES
TO PROTECT PEOPLE
WHO WANT TO KILL US.
ARCHER: IT'S A
BIG PLANET, MALCOLM.
I'M SURE THEY'RE NOT ALL
LIKE THAT.
I'M NOT AFRAID, SIR.
WHAT IF WE DID TELL THEM
THE TRUTH?
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF, CAPTAIN.
THEY'D NEVER BELIEVE US.
ARCHER: IF WE SHOW THEM
TO THE SHUTTLEPOD...
BRING THE GENERAL
UP TO ENTERPRISE...
GIVE THEM THE GRAND TOUR...
TOP IT OFF WITH DINNER
IN THE CAPTAIN'S MESS...
[ CHUCKLES ] WE'D PROBABLY
ALL HAVE A GOOD LAUGH
OVER HOW HE ALMOST SENT US
TO THE GALLOWS.
I'VE GOTTEN PLENTY OF LECTURES
ON CULTURAL CONTAMINATION.
BUT T'POL
NEVER MENTIONED ANYTHING
ABOUT SACRIFICING CREWMEN
TO PREVENT IT.
IF WE DID TELL THEM WHO WE ARE,
MAYBE IT WOULD DO THEM
A WORLD OF GOOD.
LOOK WHAT THE VULCANS
DID FOR EARTH.
THAT WAS DIFFERENT.
THESE PEOPLE HAVEN'T
EVEN SPLIT THE ATOM YET.
THE VULCANS WAITED
UNTIL WE WERE READY --
UNTIL WE HAD THE ABILITY
TO TRAVEL TO OTHER STARS.
WE'RE DOING THE RIGHT THING,
MALCOLM.
I'M SORRY YOU WON'T GET A CHANCE
TO WRITE THAT REPORT.
IT COULD STILL HAPPEN, SIR.
I'M EXPECTING A RESCUE PARTY
TO COME BARGING
THROUGH THAT DOOR ANY MOMENT.
WE'LL BE IN RANGE
OF THOSE SURVEILLANCE TOWERS
IN LESS THAN TWO MINUTES.
THEY'LL NEVER SEE US COMING.
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ]
[ KEYS JINGLING ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
MAN: ON YOUR FEET.
[ ALARM BLARES ]
WHAT WAS THAT?
THERE'S A POWER DRAIN
IN THE CLOAKING GENERATOR.
ARE THE WARP RELAYS OFFLINE?
PRIMARY AND BACKUPS.
THE WEAPON NODES ARE ACTIVE.
I THOUGHT WE DIVERTED POWER
FROM ALL THE SECONDARY SYSTEMS.
WE DID.
THEY MAY HAVE BEEN PROGRAMMED
TO REACTIVATE WHEN WE LAUNCHED.
[ ALARM BLARES ]
THREE MILITARY AIRCRAFT
OFF OUR PORT SIDE.
THEY'RE ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
TRIP: TRAVIS, CAN'T YOU HOLD
THIS THING STEADY?
IT'D BE A LOT EASIER
IF THEY STOP FIRING AT US.
COMMANDER!
STAND BY!
HE'S MY TACTICAL OFFICER.
HE CAN TELL YOU EVERYTHING
YOU WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT THE ALLIANCE'S TROOP
DEPLOYMENTS, THEIR WEAPONS.
CAPTAIN.
YOU DON'T NEED TO KILL HIM.
[ VEHICLE APPROACHING ]
UGH!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
[ GUNFIRE ]
TRIP: YOUR RIDE'S HERE.
SIR, THE PHASE PISTOL,
OUR EQUIPMENT.
DON'T LEAVE WITHOUT ME.
UGH!
AAH!
MAN: UGH!
UGH!
ARCHER: LET'S GO!
THE SHUTTLEPOD'S
RIGHT WHERE YOU LEFT IT, SIR.
WE'LL BE THERE IN TWO MINUTES.
TRIP: CAPTAIN?
REED: SIR, LOOKING FOR THIS?
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I'VE SCANNED THE REGION AHEAD.
THERE'S A BLUE-GIANT CLUSTER
THREE LIGHT-YEARS
FROM OUR CURRENT POSITION.
ARCHER: ANY PLANETS?
T'POL: NONE THAT ARE INHABITED.
SOUNDS LIKE
A NICE CHANGE OF PACE.
HAVE TRAVIS SET A COURSE.
T'POL: YES, SIR.
WAS THERE SOMETHING ELSE?
YOU TOOK A RISK
COMING DOWN ON THAT CELL SHIP.
ITS CLOAKING DEVICE
COULD HAVE FAILED.
A CALCULATED RISK.
I'M GLAD YOU DID IT.
WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS THAT
WE GOT EVERYTHING BACK --
THE COMMUNICATOR, THE PHASE
PISTOL, THE SHUTTLEPOD.
WE COULD HAVE DONE A LOT
OF DAMAGE TO THOSE PEOPLE
IF WE'D LEFT ANY OF IT BEHIND.
WE DID DO DAMAGE
TO THOSE PEOPLE.
WE'VE CHANGED THEIR PERCEPTION
OF THE ALLIANCE.
THEY NOW BELIEVE THEIR ENEMY
IS CAPABLE OF CREATING
GENETICALLY ENHANCED SOLDIERS,
NOT TO MENTION PARTICLE WEAPONS.
AND THANKS TO THAT SULIBAN SHIP,
THEY ALSO THINK THE ALLIANCE
HAS DEVELOPED
INVISIBLE AIRCRAFT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO LEAVE
TECHNOLOGY BEHIND
TO CONTAMINATE A CULTURE.
YOU WERE WILLING TO SACRIFICE
YOUR LIFE TO PROTECT THEM.
I WOULD NOT HAVE EXPECTED THAT.
AH, YOU ARE MAKING
EXCELLENT PROGRESS.
YEAH? WHAT ABOUT THIS?
OH, THAT'S NOTHING.
MAYBE NOTHING TO YOU.
GIVE IT TIME, HMM?
GIVE IT TIME.
[ SIGHS ]
THANKS, DOC.