T'POL: SCIENCE OFFICER'S LOG,
AUGUST 14, 2152.
ENTERPRISE REMAINS ON COURSE
FOR THE TRINARY SYSTEM.
I'VE TRANSMITTED
A DISTRESS CALL,
BUT THE NEAREST VULCAN SHIP
IS MORE THAN NINE DAYS AWAY.
BY THE TIME THEY ARRIVE, THEY
MAY ONLY FIND DEBRIS, IF THAT.
EVEN IF ENTERPRISE MAKES IT
PAST THE BLACK HOLE
WITHOUT BEING DESTROYED,
IT SEEMS LIKELY
THE CREW WON'T SURVIVE.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
I'M CONTINUING MY ANALYSIS
OF THE CONDITION
THAT'S STRICKEN THE CREW.
WITHOUT DR. PHLOX'S
ASSISTANCE,
I'M NOT HOPEFUL ABOUT
REVERSING ITS EFFECTS.
I'M DOCUMENTING MY FINDINGS
SO THAT STARFLEET
WILL AT LEAST HAVE A RECORD
OF WHAT HAPPENED.
THE SYMPTOMS BEGAN NOT LONG
AFTER WE SET A COURSE
FOR THE TRINARY SYSTEM.
THAT WAS NEARLY TWO DAYS AGO.
ARCHER: YOU'RE SURE
IT'S A BLACK HOLE?
T'POL: A CLASS-4.
TUCKER: ACCORDING
TO THE VULCAN STARCHARTS,
YOUR PEOPLE HAVE SURVEYED
MORE THAN 2,000 OF THESE THINGS.
T'POL: THAT'S CORRECT,
BUT NONE OF THEM
WERE PART OF A TRINARY
STAR SYSTEM.
ARCHER: HOW CLOSE CAN WE GET?
T'POL: THE GRAVITATIONAL SHEAR
BETWEEN THE STARS IS EXTREME.
WE'D HAVE TO DROP TO IMPULSE,
BUT WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO APPROACH TO WITHIN
5 MILLION KILOMETERS.
CLOSE ENOUGH TO GET
SOME NICE PICTURES.
HOW LONG WOULD IT TAKE
TO REACH THE SYSTEM AT IMPULSE?
TWO DAYS.
SET A COURSE.
TRIP.
IF YOU'VE GOT SOME FREE TIME,
I'D LOVE IT IF YOU'D TAKE
A LOOK AT MY CHAIR.
SIR?
THE CAPTAIN'S CHAIR.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
YOU MAY HAVE NOTICED
THAT I DON'T SIT
IN IT VERY MUCH.
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
IT'S UNCOMFORTABLE.
WHEN I LEAN BACK,
I FEEL LIKE I'M ABOUT
TO SLIDE OUT OF IT.
I HAVE TO SORT OF...
PERCH ON THE EDGE.
I ALWAYS ASSUMED IT WAS
THE BEST SEAT IN THE HOUSE.
TAKE A LOOK AT IT FOR ME?
I WAS GONNA PURGE
THE IMPULSE MANIFOLDS.
THE CHAIR FIRST,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
HMM.
[ BEEPING ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
-GOOD MORNING.
-MORNING.
AM I INTERRUPTING?
NO, NO, JUST THINKING
ABOUT SOMETHING.
TODAY'S DUTY ROSTER.
THANKS.
LIEUTENANT REED HAS
A NEW SECURITY PROTOCOL
HE'D LIKE TO DISCUSS WITH YOU.
I'LL DROP BY THE ARMORY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
CHEF DIDN'T REPORT FOR DUTY
THIS MORNING. HE'S ILL.
IS IT SERIOUS?
T'POL: DR. PHLOX SAID
IT'S A SIMPLE VIRUS.
HE SHOULD BE FINE
AFTER A FEW DAYS' REST.
ENSIGN SATO HAS OFFERED
TO TAKE CHARGE OF THE MESS HALL.
APPARENTLY, SHE SPENDS SOME
OF HER FREE TIME IN THE GALLEY
AND IS EAGER FOR AN OPPORTUNITY
TO COOK FOR THE CREW.
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT WITH CHEF.
LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
I RECEIVED A MANUSCRIPT
FROM EARTH...
A BIOGRAPHY OF MY FATHER.
I HAVE BEEN ASKED
TO WRITE THE PREFACE.
WOULD YOU MIND READING IT
WHEN I'M DONE?
I'D BE HAPPY TO.
IF I CAN EVER GET IT FINISHED.
I'VE BEEN PUTTING IT OFF
FOR WEEKS.
THE NEXT TWO DAYS SHOULD PROVIDE
YOU WITH AMPLE OPPORTUNITY.
IT'S NOT THAT
I HAVEN'T HAD THE TIME.
THEY ONLY ASKED FOR A PAGE.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO SUM UP
MY FATHER'S LIFE IN A PAGE?
WOULD HAVE BEEN EASIER IF THEY'D
ASKED ME TO WRITE THE BOOK.
PERHAPS, BY FOCUSING
ON ONE INCIDENT, A SINGLE EVENT
THAT EXEMPLIFIES YOUR
RELATIONSHIP WITH YOUR FATHER,
YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO CONDENSE YOUR THOUGHTS.
LOGICAL APPROACH.
MAYBE...YOU'D LIKE
TO WRITE IT FOR ME?
I AM HARDLY QUALIFIED.
CHEF WAS PLANNING TO MAKE
FRIED CHICKEN TONIGHT
WITH SCALLOPED POTATOES
AND SOME OF THE MINARAN SPINACH
WE PICKED UP ON RISA.
THE ORANGE SPINACH?
HE'S CONVINCED THERE'S A WAY
TO MAKE IT EDIBLE.
WHY DON'T WE LET HIM TACKLE THAT
WHEN HE GETS BACK?
I HAVE SOMETHING ELSE IN MIND.
IT'S ONE OF MY GRANDMOTHER'S
SPECIALTIES.
THE RECIPE'S BEEN PASSED DOWN
FOR GENERATIONS.
I'LL NEED A TRANSLATION
BEFORE I CAN PROGRAM
THE PROTEIN RESEQUENCER.
OH, NO.
YOU CAN RESEQUENCE ALL THE
CHICKEN AND POTATOES YOU WANT,
BUT I AM MAKING THIS
FROM SCRATCH.
ENSIGN...
IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
I'VE GOT A LITTLE HEADACHE --
NOTHING SERIOUS.
WHY DON'T YOU LET ME HAVE
A LOOK?
I WAS HOPING YOU COULD
JUST GIVE ME SOMETHING.
I'M RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF UPGRADING
THE NAVIGATION SENSORS.
IT WOULD BE IRRESPONSIBLE
TO DISPENSE MEDICATION
WITHOUT EXAMINING YOU FIRST.
HMM? PLEASE.
ANY OTHER SYMPTOMS --
DIZZINESS, BLURRED VISION?
-NO.
-AH.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU HAD IT?
A COUPLE OF DAYS, ON AND OFF.
WELL, I'VE BEEN MEANING
TO HAVE YOU
DROP BY SICK BAY,
IN ANY CASE, HMM?
TO SEE IF YOU'VE
HAD ANY PROBLEMS
SINCE I REMOVED
THE NEURAL IMPLANTS
YOU RECEIVED
AT THE REPAIR STATION.
YOU THINK IT COULD HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THAT?
PHLOX: OH, I NEVER
RULE OUT ANYTHING.
THEN AGAIN, IT COULD BE AS
INNOCUOUS AS MUSCULAR TENSION.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
TERRELLIAN PLAGUE STARTS OUT
WITH A SIMPLE HEADACHE...
AND THEN ALL MANNER
OF NASTY THINGS BEGIN TO HAPPEN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
[ POWER TOOL WHIRRING ]
COMMANDER.
[ WHIRRING CONTINUES ]
T'POL: COMMANDER.
PUSH IT FORWARD.
THAT'S GOOD.
HOLD IT THERE.
COMMANDER!
[ WHIRRING STOPS ]
PERHAPS YOU COULD
FINISH THAT LATER.
THIS MAY NOT BE AS GLAMOROUS
AS A BLACK HOLE,
BUT THE CAPTAIN GAVE ME
AN ORDER.
HE ALSO REQUESTED DETAILED
SENSOR READINGS
OF THIS TRINARY SYSTEM.
I THOUGHT VULCANS HAD ALL THIS
MENTAL FOCUS AND DISCIPLINE.
WE ALSO HAVE SENSITIVE HEARING.
HMM.
[ WHIRRING RESUMES ]
I'LL BE IN MY QUARTERS.
WE'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN WE'RE DONE.
REED: KEEP THOSE TARGET
DISCRIMINATORS ALIGNED.
WE DON'T WANT A TORPEDO
MISTAKING ONE
OF OUR OWN NACELLES
FOR AN ENEMY VESSEL.
ARCHER: YOU ASKED
TO SEE ME, MALCOLM?
OH, I WOULD HAVE COME
TO YOU, CAPTAIN.
IT'S NO PROBLEM.
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
I'VE BEEN REVIEWING OUR
ENCOUNTERS WITH HOSTILE SPECIES.
THE CREW'S RESPONSE
HAS BEEN ADMIRABLE,
BUT I FEEL WE CAN
DO BETTER, SIR.
AND YOU HAVE A PROPOSAL?
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
A SHIPWIDE EMERGENCY ALERT,
SOMETHING
A BIT MORE COMPREHENSIVE
THAN "BATTLE STATIONS."
WE'RE TAKING FAR TOO LONG
TO REACT TO POTENTIAL THREATS.
WITH A SINGLE ORDER FROM YOU
OR AN IMPACT TO THE HULL,
THE PLATING COULD BE POLARIZED,
WEAPONS BROUGHT ONLINE,
CRITICAL SYSTEMS SECURED --
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN,
MALCOLM,
BUT THIS ISN'T A WARSHIP.
WELL, THAT'S OBVIOUS, SIR.
DURING OUR LAST RUN-IN
WITH THE SULIBAN,
WE WERE...UNPREPARED
FOR THEIR BOARDING PARTIES.
WHEN THE MAZARITES ATTACKED,
THEY DISABLED OUR AFT SENSORS
WITH THEIR FIRST SHOT.
THE LIST GOES ON.
I CAN SEE THAT.
RUN THIS BY THE SENIOR OFFICERS,
GET SOME FEEDBACK,
AND WE'LL TALK AGAIN.
YES, SIR.
ARCHER: AND MALCOLM...
DON'T CALL IT "BATTLE STATIONS."
THINK OF SOMETHING
LESS AGGRESSIVE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
-HOW IS IT?
-REALLY GOOD. IT'S GREAT.
"CONDITION RED"?
HUH?
WHAT ABOUT "CONDITION RED"
FOR THE NEW SECURITY PROTOCOL?
WHY DON'T YOU JUST CALL IT
"SECURITY PROTOCOL"?
WELL, THAT'S NOT VERY DYNAMIC.
DO YOU THINK
A CUP HOLDER'S TOO MUCH?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
FOR THE CAPTAIN'S CHAIR.
HE JUST WANTED
THE SEAT ADJUSTED,
BUT I FIGURED, AS LONG
AS I'M WORKING ON IT...
JUST WHAT THE CAPTAIN NEEDS
IN A CRISIS --
A PLACE TO REST HIS BEVERAGE.
I'M ALSO UPGRADING
THE STATUS DISPLAYS.
HE'LL BE ABLE TO ACCESS
TACTICAL DATA FROM THE ARMREST.
IF YOU REALLY WANT TO IMPROVE
TACTICAL READINESS,
WHY DON'T YOU HELP ME
WITH THIS PROTOCOL?
I'M A LITTLE BUSY
RIGHT NOW, MALCOLM.
IT'S A CHAIR.
IT'S THE CAPTAIN'S CHAIR.
IT'S JUST AS IMPORTANT
AS YOUR...REED ALERT.
"REED ALERT"?
THAT'S NOT BAD.
ENJOYING YOUR LUNCH?
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
YEAH.
THANKS. IT WAS,
UH, TERRIFIC.
HOSHI: IT'S CALLED "ODEN."
EVERY JAPANESE FAMILY HAS
THEIR OWN WAY OF PREPARING IT.
WELL, IT SEEMS TO BE A BIG HIT.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
LIEUTENANT,
YOU BARELY TOUCHED YOURS.
UH, IT WAS LOVELY.
I'LL GET YOU A FRESH BOWL.
THAT'S NOT NECESSARY.
HOSHI: IT'S NO PROBLEM.
PLEASE. NOT HUNGRY.
ARE YOU SURE THERE'S
NOTHING WRONG WITH IT?
WELL...IT WAS A BIT SALTY.
SALTY?
OH, IT TASTES FINE.
WELL, IT JUST MUST BE ME, THEN.
REED: EVERYBODY ELSE SEEMS
TO BE ENJOYING IT.
HOW MUCH LONGER
IS THIS GOING TO TAKE?
-THAT DEPENDS.
-ON WHAT?
HOLD STILL, ENSIGN.
I HAVE TO GET BACK
TO THE BRIDGE.
WELL, I'M AFRAID YOU WON'T BE
RETURNING TO DUTY TODAY.
THE CAPTAIN NEEDS
THOSE UPGRADES, DOCTOR.
WHEN IT COMES
TO MEDICAL MATTERS,
MY AUTHORITY OVERRIDES
THE CAPTAIN'S.
I'M KEEPING YOU OVERNIGHT
FOR OBSERVATION.
BUT YOUR SCANS
DIDN'T SHOW ANYTHING.
THAT'S WHAT CONCERNS ME.
WHATEVER'S AFFLICTING YOU
MAY BE LAYING DORMANT.
I'M GOING TO RUN
A FULL BIOMOLECULAR SCAN
TO SEE IF WE CAN FIND
WHERE IT'S HIDING.
NOW, LIE...BACK
AND DON'T MOVE.
[ SIGHS ]
WHEN I WAS
ABOUT EIGHT YEARS OLD,
MY FATHER TOOK ME ON A TOUR
OF THE WARP 5 FACILITY
OUTSIDE OF BOZEMAN, MONTANA.
HE INTRODUCED ME
TO THE PEOPLE HE WORKED WITH,
SCIENTISTS WITH NAMES LIKE...
TASAKI AND COCHRANE.
AT THE TIME, I DIDN'T REALIZE
THE -- THE SIGNIFICANCE
OF THOSE NAMES
OR THE...THE SIGNIFICANCE
OF...MY FATHER'S WORK.
[ BARKS ]
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
I'LL FEED YOU IN A MINUTE.
COMPUTER, RESUME RECORDING.
[ BEEPS ]
IN A WAY...
CREATING A STABLE WARP FIELD...
MIRRORED THE...
THE F-FLUX OF EMOTIONS...
MY...FATHER FELT
WHEN HE...
EMBARKED ON...
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
[ BEEPS ]
DELETE THE LAST PARAGRAPH.
HELL, DELETE THE WHOLE THING.
[ BARKS ]
QUIET.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
HERE'S YOUR SENSOR INTERFACE.
WHAT'S THE EMERGENCY?
THIS TRINARY SYSTEM IS EMITTING
SOME UNUSUAL RADIATION.
I'M TRYING TO IDENTIFY IT.
YOU DRAGGED ME UP HERE
SO YOU COULD IDENTIFY RADIATION?
T'POL: CORRECT.
YOU SAID IT WAS URGENT.
I SAID IT WAS IMPORTANT.
I GET IT.
YOU'RE PAYING ME BACK,
MAKING ME JUMP
THROUGH HOOPS BECAUSE I WAS
MAKING TOO MUCH NOISE.
WELL, YOU'LL BE HAPPY TO KNOW
I MOVED THE CAPTAIN'S CHAIR
DOWN TO ENGINEERING,
SO IT'S NICE AND QUIET
ON THE BRIDGE NOW.
I PREFER TO WORK HERE.
I'LL NEED YOUR ASSISTANCE
WITH THIS.
WEREN'T YOU LISTENING TO ME?
I DON'T HAVE TIME
TO CATER TO YOUR WHIMS.
YOU WANT TO GET
YOUR NAME IMMORTALIZED IN
THE VULCAN DATABASE, GET SOMEONE
ELSE TO HELP YOU DO IT.
ARE YOU FEELING
ALL RIGHT, COMMANDER?
I KNOW YOU DON'T THINK
THIS CHAIR IS IMPORTANT,
BUT YOU'RE WRONG.
WHAT'S THE MOST CRITICAL
COMPONENT ON THIS SHIP?
THE MAIN COMPUTER?
THE WARP REACTOR?
HUNH-UH. IT'S THE CREW.
AND THE MOST IMPORTANT MEMBER
OF THE CREW IS THE CAPTAIN.
HE MAKES LIFE-AND-DEATH
DECISIONS EVERY DAY,
AND THE LAST THING HE
NEEDS TO BE THINKING
IN A CRITICAL SITUATION
IS, "GEE,
I WISH THIS CHAIR WASN'T
SUCH A PAIN IN THE ASS."
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
-DOCTOR?
-SHH!
-WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO --
-WAIT!
I HAVE JUST ENOUGH TIME
TO SHOWER AND GET CHANGED.
I HAVEN'T DISCHARGED YOU,
ENSIGN.
I -- I HAVEN'T SLEPT
ALL NIGHT AND I'M
SUPPOSED TO GO ON DUTY
IN 15 MINUTES.
I NEED TO PERFORM
A CEREBRAL MICRO-SECTION.
A WHAT?
LIE DOWN.
NO MORE TESTS.
I HAVE TO GET TO THE BRIDGE.
I'M GIVING YOU AN ORDER.
IF I DON'T FINISH
THOSE UPGRADES,
I COULD GET A REPRIMAND.
IT'LL BE
IN MY PERMANENT RECORD.
YOU HAVE FAR MORE TO WORRY ABOUT
THAN A BLEMISH ON YOUR RECORD.
DO YOU SEE THERE?
HMM?!
YOUR CORTICAL SCAN SHOWS
ELEVATED LEVELS OF SEROTONIN
AND SEVERAL
OTHER NEUROTRANSMITTERS.
-WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
-I'LL LET YOU KNOW
ONCE I'VE COMPLETED
THE MICRO-SECTION.
CAN'T IT WAIT
UNTIL AFTER MY SHIFT?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
IF THE CAPTAIN DOESN'T THINK
I CAN HANDLE MY DUTIES,
I'LL BE SCRUBBING
PLASMA CONDUITS ON D-DECK
FOR THE NEXT FIVE YEARS.
I COULD BE COURT-MARTIALED.
AND WHAT IF YOU'RE CARRYING
A PROTOCYSTIAN SPORE,
HMM, AND YOU INFECT
THE REST OF THE CREW?
HOW WILL THAT REFLECT
ON YOU, HMM?
OR WHAT IF YOU SUDDENLY
SUFFER A SEIZURE AT THE HELM,
BECAUSE YOU'VE CONTRACTED
ANDRONESIAN ENCEPHALITIS?
NOW, THERE IS SOMETHING
WRONG WITH YOU, ENSIGN,
AND I INTEND TO FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS.
NOT TODAY!
NOT DURING MY SHIFT!
UNLESS YOU'RE READY
TO TIE ME TO A BIO-BED,
I'M GOING BACK TO MY HELM!
AT LEAST LET ME GIVE YOU
AN ANALGESIC
FOR THE HEADACHE, HMM?
WELL, THAT'S ALL I WANTED
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
[ SIGHS ]
IF IT GETS ANY WORSE OR
YOU SUFFER ANY OTHER SYMPTOMS,
RETURN HERE IMMEDIATELY.
WHAT DID YOU...
I'VE BEEN WORKING
ON THE NEW SECURITY PROTOCOL.
OBVIOUSLY, THE REACTOR MUST BE
SECURED IMMEDIATELY
DURING A TACTICAL ALERT.
"TACTICAL ALERT"?
I CONSIDERED YOUR SUGGESTION --
"REED ALERT" --
BUT, WELL,
IT SEEMED A BIT NARCISSISTIC.
HAND ME THAT HYPERSPANNER,
WOULD YOU?
I'VE ALSO BEEN WORKING
ON A NEW ALERT SIGNAL.
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK.
[ ALARM WAILING ]
OR THIS ONE?
[ ALARM BLARES ]
[ BLARING STOPS ]
WELL, WHICH DO YOU PREFER?
FOR WHAT?
A TACTICAL ALERT.
THEY BOTH SOUND LIKE
A BAG FULL OF CATS.
WELL, THEY WERE DESIGNED
TO GET YOUR ATTENTION.
I'LL LOOK THIS OVER
AND GET BACK TO YOU.
I ALSO NEED YOUR HELP
ON AN EMERGENCY SHUTDOWN
PROCEDURE FOR THE E.P.S. GRID.
I SAID...I'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
FINE. LET'S HOPE WE DON'T
SUFFER A CATASTROPHIC
REACTOR BREACH
IN THE MEANTIME.
MALCOLM...
ONE OF YOUR BOYS BORROWED
MY LASER MICROMETER.
IF YOU'RE HEADING TO THE ARMORY,
COULD YOU GET IT BACK FOR ME?
ENSIGN, IF WE DON'T
SERVE SOMETHING SOON,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE A RIOT
ON OUR HANDS.
IS THIS TOO SALTY?
SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT.
HAND ME THE KREETASSAN SPICE.
I'LL ADD IT TO THE STOCK.
OH, AND I'M OUT OF CARROTS.
-THERE ARE 25 PEOPLE WAITING --
-CARROTS!
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
YOU'VE BEEN COOKING THE SAME
MEAL OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
I BELIEVE I'M IN CHARGE
OF THE GALLEY.
-I UNDERSTAND THAT --
-YOU'RE RELIEVED.
MA'AM --
GET OUT!
LIEUTENANT, I NEED
YOUR ASSISTANCE FOR --
CLEARANCE CODE?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
WHAT IS YOUR CLEARANCE CODE?
THE ARMORY IS A RESTRICTED AREA.
EVEN TO THE FIRST OFFICER?
HOW DO I KNOW YOU ARE
THE FIRST OFFICER?
WE'VE ENCOUNTERED SPECIES
THAT CAN ALTER THEIR APPEARANCE.
THEY COULD MASQUERADE
AS ANY ONE OF US.
I'VE ISSUED CODES
TO ALL SENIOR OFFICERS TO REVEAL
IF THE SHIP'S BEEN
INFILTRATED BY IMPOSTORS.
PART OF YOUR NEW
SECURITY PROTOCOL?
IT WAS SENT TO YOUR CONSOLE AS A
VOICE-ENCRYPTED COMMAND PACKET.
I HAVEN'T BEEN TO THE BRIDGE
FOR SEVERAL HOURS.
AS I WAS SAYING,
I NEED ASSISTANCE
ESTABLISHING A SENSOR INTERFACE
IN MY QUARTERS.
I HAVE ASKED COMMANDER TUCKER,
BUT HE BECAME...AGITATED.
IT WAS UNCHARACTERISTIC,
EVEN FOR HIM.
HAVE YOU NOTICED ANYTHING
ABNORMAL ABOUT HIS BEHAVIOR?
WHY DO YOU WANT TO ACCESS
THE SENSOR ARRAY...
FROM YOUR QUARTERS?
I WAS ASKED
TO RUN DETAILED SCANS
OF THE TRINARY STAR SYSTEM.
I WASN'T INFORMED.
IT ISN'T A TACTICAL ISSUE.
LIEUTENANT...
WHY ARE YOU ARMED?
FROM NOW ON,
SECURITY PERSONNEL ARE
TO WEAR SIDE ARMS
IN ALL RESTRICTED AREAS.
HAVE YOU CLEARED THIS
WITH THE CAPTAIN?
IT'S IN MY PROPOSAL.
HAS HE APPROVED YOUR PROPOSAL?
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO GET HIM
TO PAY CLOSER ATTENTION
TO SECURITY SINCE WE
LEFT SPACEDOCK,
BUT HE'S MORE INTERESTED
IN FRATERNIZING WITH THE CREW,
INVITING THEM TO BREAKFAST
AND TO WATCH WATER POLO.
I INTEND TO IMPLEMENT
SOME LONG-OVERDUE CHANGES,
AND IF THE CAPTAIN
WON'T APPROVE THEM,
THEN I'LL GO DIRECTLY
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
WAS THERE ANYTHING ELSE?
NO.
IT WASN'T LONG BEFORE I REALIZED
THE ODD BEHAVIOR WASN'T LIMITED
TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
IN FACT, EVERYONE I ENCOUNTERED
WAS ACTING STRANGELY,
GROWING CONSUMED WITH MATTERS
THAT SEEMED TRIVIAL, AT BEST.
I ALSO DISCOVERED
THAT, ALTHOUGH I APPEARED
TO BE IMMUNE,
THE CAPTAIN WAS NOT.
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY CHAIR?
DID YOU KNOW THAT THIS CHAIR
IS THE EXACT SAME MODEL
USED ON NEPTUNE-CLASS
SURVEY SHIPS?
IS THAT WHY YOU
CALLED ME DOWN HERE?
ENTERPRISE IS THE FIRST WARP 5
VESSEL IN HUMAN HISTORY --
THE PRIDE OF THE FLEET --
AND YOU'RE SITTING IN A CHAIR
THEY'VE BEEN USING ON
WARP 2 SHIPS FOR OVER A DECADE.
YOU DESERVE BETTER,
SO I'M STARTING FROM SCRATCH.
I'M GONNA BUILD YOU A THRONE.
STAND RIGHT THERE.
TUCKER: I NEED TO GET
A FEW PARAMETRIC SCANS
TO GET YOUR EXACT DIMENSIONS.
THIS BABY'S GONNA FIT
LIKE A GLOVE.
ISN'T THAT USED
FOR ALIGNING PHASE COILS?
YOU WON'T FEEL A THING.
LONG AS I'M DOWN HERE,
MAYBE I CAN GET YOUR OPINION.
TUCKER: DON'T MOVE.
"HOW DOES ONE MEASURE
A MAN'S LEGACY?
"IS IT DEFINED BY
THE WORKS HE'S CREATED,
"THE TECHNOLOGICAL
ADVANCES THAT WILL
FOREVER ALTER THE COURSE
OF HUMAN HISTORY?"
TURN AROUND.
[ SIGHS ]
"IF SO,
"THEN NO MAN SINCE
ZEFRAM COCHRANE HIMSELF
"HAS MADE A MORE
LASTING CONTRIBUTION
"TO THE FUTURE OF HUMANKIND
THAN MY FATHER,
DR. HENRY ARCHER."
ALL DONE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
SOUNDS GOOD.
LET ME READ YOU THE REST.
I REALLY NEED TO GET
TO WORK ON THIS.
ARCHER: IT'S JUST
A FEW MORE PAGES.
-HOW MANY MORE?
-19.
19?
ARE YOU WRITING THE PREFACE
OR THE BOOK?
I'VE GOT A LOT TO SAY.
NO KIDDING.
WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
WELL, IF I MAY, SIR...
IT'S A LITTLE LONGWINDED.
YOU'RE LUCKY
YOU'RE A DECENT ENGINEER,
BECAUSE YOU OBVIOUSLY DON'T
KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT WRITING.
I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
I HAVE 83 PEOPLE TO FEED,
NOT JUST SENIOR OFFICERS.
ALL I REQUESTED WAS A BOWL
OF PLOMEEK BROTH.
I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR SPECIAL ORDERS.
ANYWAY, YOU'LL
LIKE THIS BETTER.
ARCHER: WHERE'S LUNCH?
IT'LL BE READY
IN ONE MINUTE, SIR.
I DON'T HAVE A MINUTE.
IF YOU'RE SO HUNGRY,
FIX YOURSELF A SANDWICH.
[ CLATTERING ]
CAPTAIN, MAY I SPEAK WITH YOU?
THAT IS A VERY COMPLEX RECIPE.
I WILL NOT SERVE IT
TILL IT'S JUST RIGHT.
MY FAMILY'S REPUTATION
IS AT STAKE!
[ ALARM BLARES ]
REED: THIS IS A TACTICAL ALERT.
ALL HANDS REPORT
TO YOUR STATIONS.
[ LID THUMPS ]
I REPEAT --
THIS IS A TACTICAL ALERT.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
REPORT!
THE CREW'S RESPONSE
WAS UNACCEPTABLE.
38% OF THEM FAILED TO REPORT
TO THEIR STATIONS.
CRITICAL SYSTEMS
HAVEN'T BEEN SECURED.
I HAVEN'T EVEN HEARD
FROM ENGINEERING.
SHUT OFF THAT DAMN NOISE!
SHUT IT OFF!
I DON'T RECALL AUTHORIZING
A TACTICAL DRILL.
WELL, IT WOULDN'T BE
MUCH OF A DRILL
IF EVERYBODY KNEW
ABOUT IT, SIR.
ONE MINUTE AND 15 SECONDS.
-WHAT?
-IT TOOK YOU
ONE MINUTE AND 15 SECONDS
TO REACH YOUR POST.
I'D EXPECT MORE
OF OUR COMMANDING OFFICER,
GIVEN THAT THE CREW
JUST MIGHT FOLLOW HIS EXAMPLE.
CAPTAIN?
REED: ONE MINUTE AND 49 SECONDS.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO SEE THIS, SIR.
INTERACTIVE STATUS DISPLAYS,
SECONDARY HELM CONTROL.
IT'S EVEN GOT
INERTIAL MICRO-DAMPERS.
THE SHIP COULD BE SHAKING APART,
AND YOU'D HARDLY FEEL A THING.
REED: YOU IGNORED
A TACTICAL ALERT FOR THIS?!
I WANT TO RUN SOME COLORS
BY YOU FOR THE HEADREST.
REED: THIS IS ALL
A BIG JOKE TO YOU!
GIVE IT A REST!
THIS ISN'T A BLOODY
PLEASURE CRUISE!
WITHOUT PROPER DISCIPLINE
ON THIS SHIP,
THIS MISSION IS DOOMED!
TUCKER: WHY DON'T YOU GO PLAY
SOLDIER SOMEWHERE ELSE?
REED: IF THIS WERE
A MILITARY SITUATION,
YOU'D BE TAKEN OUT AND SHOT.
HEY! HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
I DON'T CARE WHAT COLOR
THE HEADREST IS
OR WHETHER IT CAN
SERVE ME ICED TEA!
I JUST WANT A PLACE TO SIT
WHEN I'M ON DUTY.
AND IF I HEAR THAT ALARM
ONE MORE TIME,
I MAY HAVE YOU TAKEN OUT
AND SHOT.
UNLESS THERE'S
A REAL EMERGENCY --
LIKE A REACTOR BREACH --
I DON'T WANT TO BE DISTURBED.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
GO AWAY.
DO I HAVE TO START
LOCKING MY DOOR?
YOU SAID TO INTERRUPT YOU
IF THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY.
I BELIEVE THERE IS.
IS THAT RIGHT?
THE CREW'S BEHAVIOR
HAS BECOME ERRATIC...
EVEN BY HUMAN STANDARDS.
THEY'VE GROWN DISTRACTED.
EVERYONE I'VE ENCOUNTERED
APPEARS TO BE PREOCCUPIED
WITH TRIVIAL MATTERS...
[ BEEPING ]
ENSIGN SATO'S RECIPE,
FOR EXAMPLE...
YOUR PREFACE.
WE SHOULD DECLARE
A MEDICAL EMERGENCY
AND HAVE DR. PHLOX
EXAMINE THE CREW.
I SUGGEST
HE BEGIN WITH YOU.
I'M BUSY.
-CAPTAIN.
-DISMISSED.
-YOUR CREW IS IN DANGER.
-I GAVE YOU AN ORDER.
CAPTAIN --
I SUGGEST YOU FOLLOW IT
OR I'LL HAVE YOU CONFINED
TO YOUR QUARTERS
UNTIL...UNTIL A VULCAN SHIP
CAN COME AND GET YOU.
OH, YOU'RE JUST IN TIME,
SUBCOMMANDER.
THERE'S A SURGICAL GOWN IN THE
COMPARTMENT BY THE MICROSCOPE.
HEH! THIS IS A RARE OPPORTUNITY
TO EXPLORE THE HUMAN BRAIN.
WAS HE INJURED?
HEADACHE. HEH!
AT FIRST, I THOUGHT
IT WAS A SIMPLE
VASCULAR DILATION,
BUT THEN I DISCOVERED...
A CHEMICAL IMBALANCE
IN HIS PREFRONTAL CORTEX.
I'M GOING TO BEGIN BY
EXTRACTING THE FIRST
12 MILLIMETERS
OF HIS PARIETAL LOBE.
A SUBCELLULAR ANALYSIS
OF THE TISSUE
SHOULD SHED SOME LIGHT
ON THE MYSTERY.
DOCTOR, YOU MAY WANT TO DELAY
THE PROCEDURE.
WE HAVE A LARGER PROBLEM.
THE ENTIRE CREW IS ILL.
THEY'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
YOU'VE BEEN AFFECTED AS WELL.
PLEASE REMOVE YOUR HAND.
I WON'T ASK YOU AGAIN.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN I'VE COMPLETED THE SURGERY.
MMM!
THE CREW'S BIO-SIGNS
WERE GROWING ERRATIC.
I BEGAN TO DOUBT ANY OF THEM
WOULD SURVIVE
MORE THAN A FEW HOURS.
IRONICALLY,
DR. PHLOX'S OBSESSION WITH
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER'S HEADACHE
HAS PROVIDED SOME USEFUL DATA.
HIS CEREBRAL SCANS
HAVE HELPED ME DETERMINE
THAT THE RADIATION COMING FROM
THE TRINARY SYSTEM IS CAUSING --
[ BEEPING ]
COMPUTER, PAUSE.
COMPUTER, RESUME LOG.
[ BEEPS ]
MY RADIOMETRIC ANALYSIS
IS COMPLETE.
AS I SUSPECTED,
REVERSING COURSE
WON'T TAKE US OUT OF DANGER
QUICKLY ENOUGH.
THE RADIATION APPEARS
TO EXTEND OUTWARD
AT LEAST HALF A LIGHT-YEAR
IN EVERY DIRECTION EXCEPT ONE.
IF I CAN CHART A COURSE
BETWEEN THE STARS,
WE COULD ESCAPE THE RADIATION
BEFORE THE CREW SUCCUMBS.
BUT I WON'T BE ABLE TO PILOT
THE SHIP ALONE.
CAPTAIN?
CAPTAIN ARCHER!
YOU'RE NEEDED ON THE BRIDGE.
I TOLD YOU NOT TO DISTURB ME.
WE HAVE VERY LITTLE TIME.
-WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
-YOUR CREW MAY BE DYING.
WHAT?
DO YOU REMEMBER
THAT TRINARY STAR SYSTEM?
THE ONE WITH THE BLACK HOLE?
IT'S EMITTING A DANGEROUS FORM
OF RADIATION.
IT'S AFFECTING
YOUR PREFRONTAL CORTEX.
I BELIEVE THAT'S WHY
YOU AND THE CREW
HAVE BEEN EXHIBITING
OBSESSIVE BEHAVIOR.
[ GRUNTS ]
SOME OF THE CREW'S BIO-SIGNS
ARE ALREADY UNSTABLE.
IF YOU'RE EXPOSED
TO THE RADIATION MUCH LONGER,
YOU WON'T SURVIVE.
[ GROANING ]
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TELLING YOU?
TURN IT OFF.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YES...RADIATION.
TELL...PHLOX.
IF...THE CREW IS SICK...
TELL PHLOX.
HE'S BEEN AFFECTED AS WELL.
BUT NOT YOU?
VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY
SEEMS TO BE IMMUNE.
BRING US ABOUT.
TURN THE SHIP AROUND.
IT'S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
IF WE GO BACK THE WAY WE CAME,
WE'LL SPEND TWO MORE DAYS
IN THE RADIATION FIELD.
[ GROANS ]
I'VE CHARTED A COURSE
THAT'LL HAVE US CLEAR
OF THE RADIATION
IN LESS THAN 17 MINUTES.
LOUSY COFFEE.
BUT WE'LL HAVE TO PASS
WITHIN 2 MILLION KILOMETERS
OF THE BLACK HOLE.
THERE'S CONSIDERABLE DEBRIS
AND GRAVITATIONAL SHEAR.
SOMEONE NEEDS
TO PILOT ENTERPRISE
WHILE I DETERMINE
THE COURSE CORRECTIONS.
[ GRUNTS ]
TRAVIS?
HE'S BEEN SEDATED.
I'M IN NO CONDITION TO...
FLY...A STARSHIP.
WE HAVE NO OTHER CHOICE.
[ RUMBLING ]
T'POL: MORE GRAVITATIONAL SHEAR.
WE'RE TOO FAR TO PORT.
ARCHER: BUT YOU SAID
BEARING 2.4.
12.4.
MY MISTAKE.
[ GRUNTING ]
12.4. YEAH.
HOW MUCH LONGER
IS THIS GONNA TAKE?
SIX MINUTES.
ARCHER: I'M GOOD FOR THAT.
ANOTHER SHEAR FRONT.
YOU NEED TO ROTATE
OUR LONGITUDINAL AXIS
BY 12 DEGREES
AND BRING OUR FLIGHT VECTOR
TO 014 MARK 27.
HOLD ON. HOLD ON.
ZERO WHAT?
T'POL: 014 MARK --
MARK 27.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
[ THUDDING ]
T'POL: JUST MINOR DEBRIS.
THE HULL PLATING IS HOLDING.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
OUR LATERAL VECTOR IS DRIFTING.
CAPTAIN!
HANG ON A SECOND.
I FEEL LIKE
I'M IN...FLIGHT SCHOOL AGAIN.
YOU'RE DOING WELL.
NEW HEADING.
006 MARK 4.
6...
[ ALARM BLARING ]
CAPTAIN!
I SEE IT.
WE NEED PHASE CANNONS.
THEY'D TAKE TOO LONG TO CHARGE.
[ THUDS ]
[ ALARM BLARES ]
ALL WEAPONS ARE ONLINE.
IT MUST BE PART
OF THE NEW SECURITY PROTOCOL.
FIRE!
[ GRUNTING ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
COULD YOU SHUT THAT OFF?
[ BLARING STOPS ]
HOW MUCH LONGER?
LESS THAN 10 SECONDS.
5 MORE SECONDS.
ANY MORE SURPRISES?
NOTHING ON SENSORS.
[ GROANS ]
DID WE GET SOME NICE PICTURES
OF THE BLACK HOLE?
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
A LITTLE TIRED,
BUT THE HEADACHE'S GONE.
WHAT'D YOU DO?
VERY LITTLE...FORTUNATELY.
YOU'RE, UH, FREE TO GO.
CAPTAIN.
HOW'S THE CREW?
OH, I'M CONTINUING TO MONITOR
VITAL SIGNS,
BUT I'VE DETECTED NO LINGERING
EFFECTS FROM THE RADIATION.
MOSTLY JUST RATTLED NERVES,
A FEW BRUISES AND SPRAINS
FROM WHEN SOME OF THEM
LOST CONSCIOUSNESS.
I APPRECIATE YOUR INTERVENING,
UH, BEFORE I GOT ANY FURTHER
WITH MR. MAYWEATHER'S PROCEDURE.
I WASN'T CERTAIN
IT WOULD WORK ON A DENOBULAN.
IT WORKED QUITE EFFECTIVELY,
I CAN ASSURE YOU.
W-WHAT PROCEDURE
ON MR. MAYWEATHER?
THE RADIATION AFFECTED MY
NERVOUS SYSTEM RATHER SEVERELY.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
-I'LL BE WITH YOU IN A MOMENT.
-OKAY, DOCTOR.
I'LL PROVIDE YOU
WITH A FULL REPORT
WHEN I'VE FINISHED
TREATING THE CREW.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME, CAPTAIN?
I DID.
WHEN T'POL AND I WERE NAVIGATING
THE DEBRIS FIELD,
YOUR TACTICAL ALERT WENT OFF.
I HEARD, SIR.
I'VE ALREADY DEACTIVATED
THE NEW PROTOCOLS.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE.
THEY BROUGHT THE WEAPONS ONLINE
RIGHT WHEN WE NEEDED THEM.
IF YOU HAVE NO OBJECTION,
I'D LIKE TO MAKE IT
STANDARD PROCEDURE.
NO OBJECTION, SIR.
YOU STILL NEED TO WORK
ON THAT ALARM.
I'LL GET RIGHT ON IT.
DOESN'T LOOK
ANY DIFFERENT TO ME.
GIVE IT A TRY.
[ SIGHS ]
HMM.
FEELS BETTER.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
CROSS YOUR LEGS.
SEEMS TOTALLY DIFFERENT.
I LOWERED IT...
BY ONE CENTIMETER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THAT'S ALL?
DIDN'T HAVE TIME TO INSTALL
THE NEW STATUS DISPLAYS
OR THE INERTIAL
MICRO-DAMPERS, BUT, UH,
IF YOU GIVE ME
A COUPLE OF DAYS...
I THINK THIS WILL BE FINE,
COMMANDER. THANKS.
HOW ABOUT I JUST ATTACH
THE CUP HOLDER?
THIS'LL BE FINE.
HOW DOES THIS SOUND?