[ WIND GUSTING ]
HOSHI: THESE ARE AT LEAST
300 YEARS OLDER
THAN THE ONES
IN THE LAST CHAMBER.
TUCKER: YOU SURE YOU CAN'T READ
ANY OF THIS?
HOSHI: NOPE. HOW ABOUT YOU?
TUCKER: WELL, I THINK THIS SAYS
TALL GUYS ARE POPULAR.
HOSHI: HMM, YOU'RE
A BUDDING LINGUIST.
[ TUCKER CHUCKLES ]
HOSHI: LET'S GET A SHOT
OF THAT ONE.
HOSHI: I WONDER WHAT
HAPPENED TO THEM.
TUCKER: IT IS KIND OF WEIRD.
NOT A SINGLE BIO-SIGN
ON THE ENTIRE PLANET.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
TUCKER: TUCKER.
Archer: You about finished
down there, Trip?
YOU CAN'T BELIEVE
THESE RUINS, SIR.
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
TWO DOZEN CHAMBERS.
NO TELLING
HOW MANY MORE THERE ARE.
I'M AFRAID YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO FIND OUT TODAY.
THAT STORM WE TOLD YOU ABOUT
HASN'T CHANGED COURSE.
You and Hoshi are going to need
to get back to Enterprise.
TUCKER: WE'LL JUST FINISH UP
WITH MR. TALL AND POPULAR.
WE SHOULD BACK TO THE SHUTTLEPOD
IN FIVE, SIX MINUTES.
ARCHER: DON'T TAKE
ANY LONGER THAN THAT.
ARCHER OUT.
T'POL: CAPTAIN?
WE HAVE ANOTHER STORM.
ARCHER: ANOTHER ONE?
T'POL: THE DISCHARGES
ARE MORE INTENSE.
-IT'S A GOOD DEAL BIGGER.
-AND STRONGER.
IT'S PUSHING THE FIRST STORM
THROUGH THESE MOUNTAINS
AT TWICE THE SPEED IT WAS MOVING
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
REED: THEY'RE DIAMAGNETIC
STORMS, CAPTAIN,
SATURATED WITH
POLARIC ENERGY.
ARCHER: THIS IS THE SHUTTLE?
T'POL: LESS THAN 10 KILOMETERS
FROM THE FIRST STORM.
Archer: You may not be able
to see it yet,
but it'll be coming through
the mountain pass to the north.
TUCKER: WE CAN SEE IT
JUST FINE, CAPTAIN!
THE STORMS ARE THROWING UP
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE
INTO THE ATMOSPHERE.
THE SHUTTLE'S
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
CAPTAIN, THESE RUINS
HAVE VERY THICK WALLS.
I'M SURE WE'LL BE SAFE INSIDE.
I'M AFRAID WE'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT THUNDERCLOUDS, HOSHI.
A POLARIC BURST THAT COULD
SHORT-CIRCUIT A SHUTTLEPOD
COULD DO A LOT WORSE
TO YOUR NERVOUS SYSTEM.
Hoshi: But, sir, these buildings
ARE OVER 4,000 YEARS OLD!
I'M SURE THEY'VE SURVIVED
HUNDREDS OF THESE STORMS!
I'VE SENT MALCOLM DOWN
TO THE TRANSPORTER.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
TO BRING YOU UP ONE AT A TIME.
COULDN'T WE WAIT IT OUT
INSIDE THE SHUTTLE,
POLARIZE THE HULL PLATING?
T'POL: THAT WOULD MOST LIKELY
ATTRACT A POLARIC DISCHARGE.
ARCHER: YOU HAVE TO DO THIS,
HOSHI.
There's no choice.
I'll need you clear
of the structure,
ONE AT A TIME.
UNDERSTOOD, CAPTAIN!
TUCKER: UH, LADIES FIRST.
HAVE YOU EVER DONE THIS?
TUCKER: NO, BUT THE CAPTAIN HAS,
AND MALCOLM DID IT TWICE.
THEY SAID THERE'S
NOTHING TO IT.
YOUR MOLECULES
GET PULLED APART.
THEN THEY GET PUT
BACK TOGETHER AGAIN.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY
MOLECULES YOU'RE MADE UP OF?
LOTS.
ALL RIGHT. HOW MANY?
A--A FEW TRILLION.
THAT'S A PRETTY BIG
JIGSAW PUZZLE!
WHAT IF SOME OF THE PIECES
GET PUT IN THE WRONG PLACE?
YOU KNOW, I BET A LOT OF THEM
LOOK REAL SIMILAR.
STARFLEET SAID IT'S SAFE.
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
OK, OK, BUT YOU GO FIRST,
AND IF YOU GET TO ENTERPRISE
IN ONE PIECE,
I'LL BE RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
FAIR ENOUGH.
TUCKER TO ENTERPRISE.
Reed: I read you, Commander.
READY TO GO!
COMMANDER!
Tucker: Safe and sound.
I'M ON MY WAY, SIR!
ENSIGN SATO READY FOR TRANSPORT!
REED: WELCOME TO THE CLUB.
TUCKER: HOW DO
THOSE MOLECULES FEEL?
ALL IN THE RIGHT PLACE?
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
ARCHER: NO WORSE
FOR THE WEAR, ENSIGN?
HOSHI: I GUESS YOU COULD
SAY THAT, SIR.
I'LL BE AT MY POST
IN A FEW MINUTES.
I JUST WANT TO
CLEAN UP AND CHANGE.
ARCHER: I THINK YOU'VE HAD
ENOUGH EXCITEMENT
FOR ONE AFTERNOON.
ARCHER: THE MORNING
WILL BE FINE.
THANK YOU.
I ASSUME YOU AND TRIP WILL WANT
TO FINISH YOUR SURVEY TOMORROW,
WEATHER PERMITTING.
SIR?
ARCHER: YOU LEFT A SHUTTLEPOD
DOWN THERE, REMEMBER?
SOMEBODY'S GOT TO
GO BACK AND GET IT.
I'M SURE COMMANDER TUCKER
CAN FIND SOMEONE ELSE
TO HOLD THE SECOND FLASH UNIT.
YOU WOULDN'T BE USING
THE TRANSPORTER, HOSHI.
YOU'D BE TAKING THE OTHER POD.
I DON'T WANT TO GET LOST.
ARCHER: LOST?
[ HOSHI SIGHS ]
TOO MUCH EXCITEMENT FOR ONE DAY.
I COULD REALLY USE SOME REST,
SIR.
SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
REED: SO HE TELLS HER, "IT WAS
MERELY A WARP IMBALANCE."
TUCKER: THAT'S A LIE, MALCOLM.
REED: WE ALL HEARD IT,
COMMANDER.
THERE'S NO USE PRETENDING.
TUCKER: COME ON, TRAVIS...
ANYONE SITTING HERE?
BUT THAT'S WHAT
YOU SAID, THOUGH.
NO, NO.
HOSHI: AHEM!
IS ANYONE SITTING HERE?
TUCKER: NO. PLEASE.
MAYWEATHER: SO WHAT WAS IT LIKE?
REED: TRAVIS...LET HER
EAT HER SUPPER.
HOSHI: IT WAS VERY UNSETTLING.
DIDN'T YOU FIND IT UNSETTLING?
TUCKER: WELL,
FOR A MINUTE OR TWO.
BUT ONCE I COUNTED
MY FINGERS AND TOES...
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST DON'T FEEL RIGHT.
IT WAS PROBABLY THAT STORM.
YOU DON'T FORGET THINGS
LIKE THAT TOO QUICKLY.
IT'S NOT THE STORMS.
IT'S THE TRANSPORTER.
I DON'T FEEL LIKE MYSELF
SINCE I WENT THROUGH IT.
YOU KNOW, I NEED TO CHECK
THE MEDICAL DATABASE
AND FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE PEOPLE THEY USED
WHEN THEY WERE TESTING
THAT THING.
YOU MEAN OTHER
THAN CYRUS RAMSEY?
CYRUS RAMSEY?
TUCKER: AH, DON'T TELL ME YOU
DON'T KNOW ABOUT POOR CYRUS?
AM I SUPPOSED TO?
MAYWEATHER: YOU CAN'T GO ON
A SURVIVAL OVERNIGHT
WITHOUT HEARING A STORY
ABOUT SOMEONE SEEING
RAMSEY'S MOLECULES
REMATERIALIZING
ON A FOGGY NIGHT.
HMM.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
NEXT THING YOU'LL TELL US
YOU NEVER HEARD
OF THE EASTER BUNNY.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
MADISON, WISCONSIN--
MAY, I THINK--2146.
HE WAS THE TEST SUBJECT FOR
THE FIRST LONG-RANGE TRANSPORT:
JUST 100 METERS.
SOMETHING WENT WRONG
WITH THE PATTERN BUFFER.
HE NEVER REMATERIALIZED.
REED: COME ON, HOSHI.
EVERYBODY'S HEARD
OF CYRUS RAMSEY.
I MUST HAVE FALLEN ASLEEP
BEFORE THE GHOST STORIES.
WHERE DID YOU DO
YOUR SURVIVAL TRAINING?
MAYWEATHER: DEATH VALLEY,
CALIFORNIA.
MIDDLE OF JULY, NATURALLY.
YOU?
TUCKER: CAPTAIN AND I
WERE IN THE SAME GROUP--
ALICE SPRINGS, AUSTRALIA.
NEVER SAW SO MANY FLIES
IN MY LIFE...
[ CHUCKLES ]
TUCKER: THE BITING KIND.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
TUCKER.
Archer: The storms
are breaking up.
I don't think
we'll have any trouble
getting you back down
in the morning.
TRAVIS WAS JUST TELLING ME
HE'D LIKE TO SEE THE RUINS.
Archer: Well, I don't think
Hoshi will be joining you.
TUCKER: I'LL NEED A PALLET
TO BRING THE OTHER POD BACK.
Archer: Travis, it is.
I'll see you both
in the morning.
Archer out.
TUCKER: NEVER SAY
I DON'T TAKE YOU ANYWHERE.
MAYWEATHER: YOU DON'T TAKE ME
ANYWHERE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
SEE YOU LATER.
DOCTOR?
DR. PHLOX?
-HELLO?
-AH, ENSIGN.
SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
I JUST LOOKED IN THERE.
WERE YOU IN THERE?
DID YOU HEAR ME COME IN?
I WAS FEEDING MY LEECHES.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YOU DIDN'T HEAR ME?
I'M RIGHT HERE, ENSIGN.
ARE YOU NOT FEELING WELL?
NO, I'M NOT FEELING WELL.
I DEMATERIALIZED,
AND THEN I REMATERIALIZED
AND...NO, I'M NOT FEELING WELL.
I HEARD ABOUT YOUR ORDEAL
ON THE SURFACE.
THOSE STORMS SOUNDED TERRIFYING.
DOCTOR, I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT THE STORMS.
I'M TALKING ABOUT MY MOLECULES.
HMM, COME SIT DOWN.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
MM-HMM. YEAH.
IT'LL TAKE ME A WHILE
TO ACCOUNT FOR EVERY MOLECULE,
BUT YOU APPEAR TO BE
IN ONE PIECE.
I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE IN DANGER
OF BECOMING THE NEXT
CYRUS RAMSEY.
DON'T TELL ME THEY TALK
ABOUT HIM ON DENOBULA?
OH, I SPENT NEARLY NINE MONTHS
ON EARTH, REMEMBER?
I JUST DON'T FEEL RIGHT.
EVER SINCE THE TRANSPORT,
I'VE BEEN SHAKY, NOT MYSELF.
NOT A SINGLE
BIOMOLECULAR ANOMALY.
NO? HOW ABOUT THIS?
A SUBCUTANEOUS PIGMENTATION.
IT'S NOT WHERE IT USED TO BE.
IT WAS A GOOD CENTIMETER LOWER.
WELL, IT LOOKS LOVELY
WHERE IT IS NOW.
IT'S NOT A JOKE, DOCTOR.
IF THAT MACHINE COULD
MOVE A BIRTHMARK,
WHO KNOWS WHAT ELSE IT COULD DO?
I'M TELLING YOU,
I DON'T FEEL RIGHT.
I HAVE A LOT OF ANIMALS TO FEED
BEFORE BEDTIME.
IF I WERE YOU, I'D GET
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP, HMM?
[ SIGHS ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
HELLO?
T'Pol: You're needed
on the bridge, Ensign.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
T'Pol: 1100 hours.
There's been an emergency.
1100 HOURS--
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
MY SHIFT STARTS AT 0800.
T'Pol: Now, Ensign.
HOSHI: I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
ARCHER: TUCKER AND MAYWEATHER
HAVE BEEN TAKEN HOSTAGE.
TRIP GOT OFF
A SHORT MESSAGE,
BUT WE HAVEN'T HEARD
ANYTHING IN THE LAST HOUR.
HOSHI: TAKEN HOSTAGE BY WHO?
ARCHER: THE PEOPLE DOWN THERE
DIDN'T LIKE YOU
DISTURBING THEIR RUINS.
HOSHI: PEOPLE? THERE WASN'T
A BIO-SIGN ON THE PLANET!
T'POL: THE CHAMBERS YOU
AND MR. TUCKER PHOTOGRAPHED
CONTAINED SACRED RELICS.
HOW COULD YOU
POSSIBLY KNOW THAT?
ARCHER: HAVE YOU FOUND
THEIR BIO-SIGNS?
THEY'RE STILL IN THE COMPLEX.
I'M TRYING TO ISOLATE
THE SPECIFIC CHAMBER.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
IT'S MAYWEATHER'S COMMUNICATOR.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD, TRAVIS.
[ ALIEN SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
ARCHER: ENSIGN?
I NEED MORE.
ARCHER: THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
WE APOLOGIZE
IF WE'VE TRESPASSED.
MY CREWMEN DIDN'T
MEAN ANY HARM.
[ ALIEN SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
I'M SORRY, SIR,
IT'S NOT WORKING.
I'M GOING TO NEED MORE.
CAN I SPEAK TO ONE
OF MY OFFICERS?
[ ALIEN SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
IT'S NOT GOING TO GET
MUCH BETTER THAN THAT.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
FORGET ABOUT THE U.T.
JUST TRY AND TALK TO THEM.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
[ ALIEN SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
[ ALIEN SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
IF I WENT BACK
TO THE UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR,
MAYBE I COULD...
ARCHER: YOU ALREADY TRIED THAT.
TALK TO THEM.
-I CAN'T.
-LIVES ARE AT STAKE, ENSIGN.
I KNOW. I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT HE'S SAYING.
I'M--I'M SORRY.
I'M...SORRY.
ARCHER: NO NEED TO APOLOGIZE.
WHY DON'T YOU GO BACK TO
YOUR QUARTERS AND GET SOME REST.
CAPTAIN, I REALIZE I OVERSLEPT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW IT HAPPENED.
BUT, PLEASE,
I DON'T WANT TO GO
BACK TO MY QUARTERS.
-TAKE THE COM.
-AYE, CAPTAIN.
MALCOLM?
[ SHOWER RUNNING ]
[ GASPS ]
HOSHI: ANYONE SITTING HERE?
SUBCOMMANDER?
-AHEM!
-ENSIGN.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO JOIN ME?
HOSHI: THANK YOU.
I WOULD'VE THOUGHT
YOU'D BE ON THE BRIDGE.
WHY IS THAT?
COMMANDER TUCKER, TRAVIS?
THE HOSTAGE SITUATION
WAS RESOLVED.
THEY'RE BACK ON BOARD.
IT'S ONLY BEEN AN HOUR
SINCE I LEFT THE BRIDGE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
CREWMAN BAIRD DECIPHERED
THEIR LANGUAGE.
A SIMPLE BIMODAL SYNTAX.
I--I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW.
WITH THE UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
I RAN EVERY LINGUISTIC
ALGORITHM.
WHEN THE CAPTAIN AGREED TO
RETURN THE SOIL AND ROCK SAMPLES
AND DESTROY THE PHOTOGRAPHS
THAT WERE TAKEN,
THE HOSTAGES WERE RELEASED.
IF WE HAVE DECRYPTED
THE LANGUAGE,
I SHOULD GET BACK TO THE BRIDGE.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THE CAPTAIN MIGHT
WANT TO SPEAK WITH THEM AGAIN.
T'POL: CAPTAIN ARCHER HAS ASKED
THAT YOU REMAIN OFF DUTY
FOR THE TIME BEING.
CREWMAN BAIRD HAS BEEN PLACED
IN CHARGE OF COMMUNICATIONS.
ALISON: AFTER LUNCH,
YOU SHOULD TAKE A LOOK
AT THE SECONDARY COUPLINGS.
THEY'RE GOING TO NEED
TO BE ALIGNED.
HOSHI: ALISON.
ALISON: START ON C-DECK,
THEN WORK YOUR WAY DOWN.
CREWMAN: YES, MA'AM.
[ SILENCE ]
REED'S VOICE:
THE STREAM'S TOO UNSTABLE.
TUCKER'S VOICE: COME ON, HOSHI.
WHAT?
[ BEEP, DOOR CLOSES ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
HOSHI: CAN YOU SEE ME?
-ENSIGN?
-CAN YOU SEE ME?
PHLOX: IS THERE SOMETHING
IN PARTICULAR
YOU'D LIKE ME TO LOOK AT?
HOSHI: SOMETHING'S WRONG,
DOCTOR. SOMETHING'S VERY WRONG.
EVER SINCE I USED
THAT TRANSPORTER,
NOTHING HAS BEEN THE WAY
THAT IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE.
I COULDN'T TRANSLATE
A SIMPLE BIMODAL SYNTAX,
BUT CREWMAN BAIRD COULD.
CREWMAN BAIRD DOESN'T KNOW
THE FIRST THING
ABOUT OUR LINGUISTIC DATABASE.
AND CAPTAIN ARCHER TOLD ME
TO STAY IN MY QUARTERS,
BUT MY MIRROR DOESN'T WANT
TO GIVE ME A SOLID REFLECTION,
AND MY SHOWER CAN'T DECIDE
WHETHER TO BOUNCE OFF ME
OR GO THROUGH ME.
AND NOBODY WANTS TO TALK TO ME.
SOMETIMES, I THINK THEY DON'T
EVEN SEE THAT I'M THERE.
THE TURBOLIFT CONTROL
WON'T EVEN RESPOND TO ME.
WELL, I SEE YOU, ENSIGN.
AND THE SICKBAY DOORS
RESPONDED WHEN YOU CAME IN.
TRANSPORTER TECHNOLOGY
IS VERY NEW.
I'M SURE HUMANS
WERE EQUALLY FRIGHTENED
WHEN THE AUTOMOBILE WAS
INTRODUCED, OR THE AIRPLANE.
NEW FORMS OF TRANSPORT
TAKE A WHILE TO GET USED TO.
I'M NOT AT ALL SURPRISED
AT YOUR REACTION.
YOU WOULDN'T CATCH ME
USING THAT APPARATUS.
BUT I...
I CAN PROMISE YOU ONE THING.
YOU'RE IN PERFECT HEALTH.
YOU'RE NEITHER TRANSPARENT
NOR POROUS.
YOU WON'T PUT THIS ON
MY MEDICAL RECORD, WILL YOU?
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
I DIDN'T EVEN SEE YOU
COME IN HERE.
NOT FUNNY, DOCTOR.
I WOULD LIKE TO GIVE YOU
A MILD SEDATIVE, HMM?
IT'LL HELP YOU GET
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME TO YOU,
THE LAST THING I NEED RIGHT NOW
IS TO BE MEDICATED.
PHLOX: AS YOU WISH.
BUT STOP BY IN THE MORNING,
ALL RIGHT?
FIRST THING.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
YOU'RE UPSIDE DOWN, ENSIGN.
HOSHI: I WAS TAUGHT
NEVER TO CONTRADICT
A SUPERIOR OFFICER.
THE CAPTAIN TOLD ME
WHAT HAPPENED.
DID THEY TREAT
YOU ALL RIGHT?
DIDN'T EVEN TIE US UP.
AS SOON AS THE CAPTAIN PROMISED
TO GIVE THEM THEIR STUFF BACK,
THEY WALKED US
TO THE SHUTTLEPODS,
AND AWAY WE WENT.
HOSHI: I'M SORRY I WASN'T
MORE HELPFUL
TRYING TO TRANSLATE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
TUCKER: WELL, WE'RE SAFE
AND SOUND.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
HAVE YOU TRIED THIS THING?
HOSHI: I GET MOTION
SICKNESS, REMEMBER?
[ TUCKER CHUCKLES ]
HAVE YOU FELT OK SINCE WE WERE
TRANSPORTED YESTERDAY?
TUCKER: CONSIDERING THAT I'VE
BEEN BACK DOWN TO THE SURFACE,
KIDNAPPED AND RELEASED,
I'VE PROBABLY HAD BETTER DAYS.
WHY, ARE YOU NOT FEELING WELL?
I DIDN'T THINK I WAS.
BUT THE DOCTOR SEEMS TO FEEL
MY SYMPTOMS ARE PSYCHOLOGICAL.
WHAT KIND OF SYMPTOMS?
I JUST HAVEN'T BEEN MYSELF.
EVERYTHING'S A LITTLE OFF...
[ SIGHS ]
EVEN THE LAWS OF PHYSICS.
WELL, IN THAT CASE,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU SHOULDN'T GET ON THIS THING.
THE LAWS OF PHYSICS
DON'T APPLY IN HERE, EITHER.
SORRY.
JUST TRYING TO CHEER YOU UP.
IT'S OK.
PHLOX PROMISES ME I'LL BE FINE.
IT'S GOING TO BE A WHILE
BEFORE ANY OF US
GETS USED TO BEING...
TAKEN APART
AND PUT BACK TOGETHER AGAIN.
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY NATURAL
TO BE ANXIOUS ABOUT IT.
I HOPE IT'S JUST A QUESTION
OF BEING ANXIOUS.
WELL, WHAT ELSE COULD IT BE?
I SAW MY REFLECTION
BECOME TRANSPARENT.
I SAW WATER PASS RIGHT THROUGH
MY HAND.
I'M NOT CONVINCED
THAT THE TRANSPORTER PUT ME BACK
THE WAY IT'S SUPPOSED TO.
ALL THE KING'S HORSES
AND ALL THE KING'S MEN.
I CAN SEE WHY YOU MIGHT IMAGINE
THE UNIVERSE UNRAVELING.
IF YOU'RE AFRAID YOU HAVEN'T
BEEN PUT BACK TOGETHER RIGHT,
WHY ASSUME ANYTHING
ELSE MAKES SENSE?
IF I WERE YOU,
I'D ASK THE DOC FOR A SEDATIVE.
NOTHING LIKE CRAWLING INTO BED.
YOU MEN ARE ALL ALIKE.
NO, WAIT AND SEE.
A NIGHT'S SLEEP WILL DO YOU
A WORLD OF GOOD.
HOSHI: THANK GOD YOU'RE HERE.
I'VE BEEN STUCK IN HERE
FOR HOURS.
THE DOOR CONTROL IS...
TUCKER: SHE WAS HERE LAST NIGHT,
RIGHT OVER THERE.
COMMANDER?
T'POL: T'POL TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
Archer: Go ahead.
T'POL: HAVE THE SECURITY
DETAILS REPORTED BACK?
Archer: No sign of her yet.
T'POL: WE'VE COVERED THE FORWARD
SECTION OF C-DECK.
-SHE'S NOT HERE.
-YES, SHE IS.
TUCKER: HAVE YOU TRIED
THE BIO-SEARCHES AGAIN, CAPTAIN?
Archer: Still nothing.
TUCKER: WELL, I'LL GO TAKE
A LOOK AT THEM.
Archer: I'm going to maintain
our present orbit
until Hoshi turns up.
T'Pol, meet me in Sickbay
right away.
T'POL: YES, SIR.
PHLOX: SHE CAME TO SICKBAY
AFTER THE INCIDENT
WITH THE STORM,
THEN A SECOND TIME
EARLY LAST NIGHT.
ARCHER: SHE WASN'T FEELING WELL?
PHLOX: SHE SAID SHE FELT SHAKY.
YOU'RE AWARE THAT WAS THE FIRST
TIME SHE'D EVER TRANSPORTED?
T'POL: QUITE AWARE.
PHLOX: I BELIEVED THAT WAS
THE SOURCE OF HER ANXIETY.
SHE WAS CONVINCED
HER MOLECULES
HADN'T BEEN REASSEMBLED
PROPERLY.
I SHOULD'VE TAKEN HER
MORE SERIOUSLY.
THESE ARE
THE BIOMOLECULAR SCANS
I TOOK DURING EACH
OF HER TWO VISITS.
THEY SEEMED PERFECTLY
NORMAL AT THE TIME.
WHEN I HEARD
SHE WAS MISSING,
SOMETHING MADE ME
TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
YOU SEE THESE
PROTEIN FILAMENTS?
NOW LOOK AT...THIS.
ARCHER: I'M GOING TO NEED
SOME HELP HERE, PHLOX.
PHLOX: LOOK HOW MUCH
HER SUBCELLULAR MEMBRANES
HAVE DEGRADED.
THESE SCANS WERE TAKEN
LESS THAN 24 HOURS APART.
IT'S VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S IMPOSSIBLE?
T'POL: ENSIGN SATO
WASN'T IMAGINING IT.
HER MOLECULES
ARE COMING APART.
IT'S THE SECONDARY PHASE COILS.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT THEM?
THEY'RE NOT ALIGNING.
THEY'RE NOT PERFECTLY
SYNCHRONIZED.
IT MUST'VE HAPPENED RIGHT AFTER
I CAME UP FROM THE SURFACE.
PHLOX: IF THEY'RE NOT
PERFECTLY SYNCHRONIZED?
T'POL: THE RESEQUENCING
WOULD START TO DISSIPATE.
WITHIN HOURS, SHE'LL LOSE
MOLECULAR COHESION.
TUCKER: SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO GO FIRST.
I TOLD HER I WOULDN'T
LEAVE HER ALONE
WITH THAT STORM COMING,
BUT SHE INSISTED
ON GOING SECOND.
SHE WANTED TO BE SURE IT WAS
WORKING, THAT IT WAS SAFE.
I'M THE ONE
WHO SHOULD BE MISSING.
I TOLD HER TO GO FIRST.
SHE SHOULD'VE LISTENED TO ME.
T'POL: IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
ARCHER: TAKE THE TRANSPORTER
OFF-LINE
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT WENT WRONG.
STARFLEET PROMISED ME THIS
SORT OF THING WOULDN'T HAPPEN.
AYE, SIR.
PHLOX: CAPTAIN, IF THERE WAS
A LOSS OF MOLECULAR COHESION,
I'M AFRAID WE SHOULDN'T BE
LOOKING FOR HOSHI, PER SE.
ARCHER: WHAT SHOULD WE
BE LOOKING FOR?
PHLOX: SUBCELLULAR RESIDUE.
THERE WOULDN'T BE
ANYTHING LEFT BY NOW
EXCEPT FOR SUBCELLULAR RESIDUE.
YOU'RE WRONG, DOCTOR.
I'M STILL IN ONE PIECE.
YOU JUST CAN'T SEE ME.
ARCHER: HAVE THE DOCTOR HELP YOU
RECALIBRATE THE SENSORS.
THEN START SCANNING
FOR THIS...
RESIDUE.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO MAYWEATHER.
Mayweather: Go ahead, sir.
PREPARE TO BREAK ORBIT
AND RESUME PREVIOUS COURSE.
Mayweather: Aye, Captain.
I'LL BE IN MY READY ROOM.
PHLOX: THERE'S NO WAY TO BE
CERTAIN THIS IS HER.
TUCKER: IS IT HOSHI'S D.N.A.
OR ISN'T IT?
PHLOX: IT'S DIFFICULT TO TELL.
THE AMINO ACIDS
HAVE BROKEN DOWN.
HOSHI: DON'T WASTE YOUR TIME.
IT'S NOT ME.
TUCKER: THE INTERNAL SCAN SAID
"ACCESS SHAFT B7."
SHE'S GOT TO BE
HERE SOMEWHERE.
IF YOU SPENT A LITTLE MORE TIME
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO...
[ INDISTINCT ALIEN VOICE ]
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
TUCKER'S VOICE:
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
REED'S VOICE:
THE STREAM'S TOO UNSTABLE.
LIEUTENANT?
REED'S VOICE:
YOU CAN DO IT, ENSIGN.
IT'S AS EASY AS ONE, TWO...
TUCKER: HERE, DOC.
OVER HERE.
[ SCANNER BEEPS ]
TUCKER: WHAT DO YOU THINK?
PHLOX: TRY ISOLATING
THE DIPEPTIDES.
NOW RUN A COMPARISON
WITH HER GENETIC PROFILE.
TUCKER: WHY WOULD SHE HAVE
COME DOWN HERE?
PHLOX: I DOUBT WE'LL EVER KNOW,
COMMANDER.
WELL, CAPTAIN ARCHER WILL
WANT HOSHI'S PARENTS
TO HAVE THIS.
THEY'RE BOTH ALIVE,
AREN'T THEY?
TUCKER: YEAH, BOTH ALIVE.
YOU GO AHEAD, DOC.
I'M GOING TO...
I'M GOING TO STICK
AROUND FOR A MINUTE.
PHLOX: I UNDERSTAND.
[ SIGHS ]
HOSHI.
YOU CAN SEE ME?
I SHOULD'VE MADE YOU GO FIRST.
WHAT COULD I HAVE BEEN THINKING
LEAVING YOU DOWN THERE?
I WAS THE RANKING OFFICER,
AND I HAD NO BUSINESS
LEAVING A SUBORDINATE
IN THE PATH OF THOSE STORMS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
LISTEN TO ME?
I TOLD YOU WE'D BE SAFE.
AND NOW LOOK WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
[ TUCKER SIGHS ]
[ ALIEN SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ CONVERSING
IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
HOSHI: CAPTAIN, I NEED YOU
TO LISTEN TO ME.
THERE ARE ALIENS
ON BOARD FROM THE SURFACE.
THEY'RE PLANTING
BOMBS ON D-DECK.
YOU'VE GOT TO HEAR ME.
THE SHIP IS IN DANGER.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
Baird: We've located
her father, sir.
The mother isn't home.
ARCHER: WHAT TIME IS IT THERE?
Baird: 0900.
ARCHER: PUT HIM THROUGH.
GOOD MORNING, SIR.
Captain Archer.
Is everything all right?
NO, SIR, EVERYTHING...
IS NOT ALL RIGHT.
WE'VE HAD AN ACCIDENT
WITH OUR TRANSPORTING DEVICE.
Transporting device?
What is that?
HOSHI: YOU DON'T
HAVE TIME FOR THIS.
ARCHER: A MATTER-STREAM
CONVERTER.
IT WAS APPROVED FOR
TRANSPORTING BIO-MATTER
BEFORE WE LEFT EARTH.
GOT TO FIND SOMETHING
THAT'LL GET YOUR ATTENTION.
ARCHER: WE'VE USED IT
A NUMBER OF...
Sato: Bio-matter?
What are you referring to,
produce or people?
ARCHER: I'M JUST TRYING
TO EXPLAIN TO YOU
THAT STARFLEET TOLD US
IT WAS SAFE.
So Hoshi is safe.
ARCHER: NO, SIR.
THERE WAS AN ACCIDENT.
SHE BEGAN TO...
HER MOLECULES
BEGAN TO DESTABILIZE.
Sato: Her molecules?
What are you talking about,
Captain?
ARCHER: THIS ISN'T EASY, SIR.
I FOUGHT TO GET HOSHI
TO COME ON THIS MISSION.
I'M RESPONSIBLE
FOR HER BEING OUT HERE.
SHE'S BECOME
A MEMBER OF OUR FAMILY.
Sato: Family?
We're her family, not you.
Why are you calling me?
To say that she has become
a member of your family?
I'm sorry, Captain.
You are not making any sense.
WE LOST HOSHI TODAY,
MR. SATO.
I WISH I DIDN'T HAVE
TO TELL YOU THAT.
You are saying Hoshi is dead?
-I'M SORRY, SIR.
-WE'RE ALL GOING TO BE DEAD
IF I CAN'T GET HIM
TO NOTICE THIS.
Maybe you could
call us back later.
This afternoon?
HOW ABOUT MORSE CODE?
YOU KNOW MORSE CODE, DON'T YOU?
I must have time to speak
with Hoshi's mother.
-COME ON, LISTEN.
-THIS AFTERNOON.
HOSHI: CAN YOU HEAR IT?
I'M SO SORRY.
So am I.
COME ON.
[ MORSE CODE CLICKING ]
HOSHI: THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE MAKING THAT NOISE, IS IT?
LISTEN, YOU CAN HEAR IT.
S-O-S. S-O-S--
IT'S A CALL FOR HELP.
I NEED YOU TO HEAR IT.
ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'Pol: Yes, Captain?
COULD YOU COME IN HERE
FOR A MINUTE?
T'Pol: Right away.
THAT'S RIGHT, SHOW IT TO HER.
ONE OF YOU WILL FIGURE IT OUT.
ARCHER: LOOK AT THIS.
I'VE NEVER HEARD IT
MAKE THAT NOISE BEFORE.
T'POL: A PLASMA CIRCUIT'S
BEING INTERRUPTED.
I'LL ASK COMMANDER TUCKER
TO TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
ARCHER: LISTEN TO THE PATTERN.
THREE DOTS, THREE DASHES,
THREE DOTS.
S-O-S.
T'POL: DOTS?
ARCHER: DOTS AND DASHES--
MORSE CODE.
ITS BEEN USED ON EARTH
FOR CENTURIES.
IT'S A DISTRESS CALL.
HOSHI: LET'S SEE HOW GOOD
YOUR MEMORY IS.
H...O...
T'POL: IT'S CHANGED.
HOSHI: S...
H...
ARCHER: IT STILL SOUNDS
LIKE MORSE CODE.
HOSHI: I. COME ON.
T'POL: THIS PLASMA CIRCUIT
IS SELF-CONTAINED.
NO ONE OUTSIDE OF THIS ROOM
COULD BE USING IT
TO SEND A MESSAGE.
HOSHI: I'M NOT OUTSIDE
THIS ROOM, I'M RIGHT HERE.
T'POL: IT'S BEEN
A VERY DIFFICULT DAY.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
TRY TO GET SOME REST.
ARCHER: YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'LL HAVE TRIP
LOOK AT IT TOMORROW.
HOSHI: TOMORROW'S TOO LATE!
THEY'RE GOING TO BLOW UP
THE SHIP! CAPTAIN!
[ ALIENS CONVERSE
IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ CONVERSING IN
NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
HOSHI: NO, WAIT!
TUCKER'S VOICE:
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
WHAT?
REED'S VOICE:
THE STREAM'S TOO UNSTABLE.
TUCKER'S VOICE:
COME ON, HOSHI. COME ON.
REED'S VOICE:
YOU CAN DO IT, ENSIGN.
IT'S AS EASY AS ONE, TWO...
REED: THREE.
TUCKER: NICE WORK, MALCOLM.
SEE, I TOLD YOU,
PIECE OF CAKE.
HOSHI: WHERE ARE THEY?
WE'VE GOT TO STOP THEM.
TUCKER: WHO?
HOSHI: YOU HEARD ME?
YOU CAN HEAR ME?
DO YOU SEE ME?
-EVERYTHING'S FINE, HOSHI.
-IT'S NOT FINE.
THEY PUT BOMB
ON THE WARP REACTOR!
-WHO?
-THE ALIENS FROM THE SURFACE.
THERE'S NO ONE ON THE SURFACE.
IT'S UNINHABITED.
HOSHI: WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THEY KIDNAPPED YOU AND TRAVIS!
WE'VE GOT TO STOP THEM!
REED: HOSHI, THE TRANSPORTER
WAS AFFECTED BY THE STORMS.
I HAD SOME TROUBLE REINTEGRATING
YOUR MATTER STREAM.
HOSHI: TROUBLE?
TUCKER: YOU WERE SORT OF...
TRAPPED IN THE PATTERN BUFFER,
BUT ONLY FOR A FEW SECONDS.
8.3 SECONDS, TO BE PRECISE.
HOSHI: ARE YOU SAYING THAT I
WAS JUST ON THE SURFACE?
TUCKER: YOU INSISTED ON
GOING SECOND.
DO YOU HAVE A MIRROR?
WHAT?
FORGET IT.
AND I WAS SURE I WAS GOING
TO BE THE NEXT CYRUS RAMSEY.
CYRUS WHO?
SO YOU'RE SAYING ALL OF THAT
HAPPENED IN EIGHT SECONDS?
PHLOX: ACTUALLY, IT PROBABLY
HAPPENED IN THE LAST
ONE OR TWO SECONDS...AS YOUR
MATTER STREAM WAS COALESCING.
SHE SEEMS FINE.
ARCHER: MALCOLM IS RECOMMENDING
SOME NEW TRANSPORT PROTOCOLS
TO STARFLEET.
HE'S SUGGESTING WE START
COMPRESSING THE TRANSPORT BEAM.
HOSHI: WELL, I HOPE YOU DON'T
PLAN ON BEAMING ME ANYWHERE
FOR A LONG TIME.
ARCHER: BUT YOU SAID YOU STEPPED
ONTO THE ALIENS' TRANSPORTER
BY CHOICE.
HOSHI: I WAS TRYING
TO SAVE ENTERPRISE.
ARCHER: SOUNDS LIKE
YOU OVERCAME YOUR FEAR.
HOSHI: IT'S ALL IN MY HEAD,
REMEMBER?
ARCHER: DOES IT MATTER?
YOU WERE AFRAID OF GETTING LOST,
AFRAID OF DISAPPEARING...
BUT YOU STILL CLIMBED
ONTO THAT PLATFORM,
REAL OR NOT.
HOSHI: IF IT'S ALL THE SAME
TO YOU, SIR,
I'D LIKE TO STICK TO SHUTTLEPODS
FOR THE TIME BEING.
ARCHER: COME ON.
LET'S GO TO THE BRIDGE.
HOSHI: CAPTAIN--AHEM--
IF YOU DON'T MIND...
[ DOOR OPENS ]