[ HARMONICA PLAYING ]
[ ENGINES SLOWING ]
Archer: Archer to
Commander Tucker.
GO AHEAD.
I know you're off-duty,
but we've got visitors.
I CAN SEE THAT.
Are you up
for a little repair work?
SIR?
Meet me at docking port 2.
ON MY WAY.
MAN: ♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ANYTHING SERIOUS?
ARCHER: THEY SAID
THEY WERE HAVING TROUBLE
WITH ONE OF THEIR
LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
TRIP: WHO'S "THEY"?
T'POL: RETELLIAN CARGO PILOTS.
THE SEAL IS SECURE.
WELCOME ABOARD.
ALIEN: GRACIOUS OF YOU
TO HELP US, CAPTAIN.
WE WERE BEGINNING TO THINK
OUR DISTRESS CALL
WOULD NEVER BE ANSWERED.
ARCHER: THIS IS
SUBCOMMANDER T'POL
AND MY CHIEF ENGINEER,
COMMANDER TUCKER.
ALIEN: OUR SALVATION.
TRIP: THE CAPTAIN SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT LIFE SUPPORT.
WE WERE HIRED
TO RETURN A YOUNG WOMAN
TO HER HOMEWORLD.
A FEW DAYS AGO,
HER STASIS POD
BEGAN TO MALFUNCTION.
ARCHER: STASIS?
IS SHE INJURED?
NO, NO.
SHE'S A PASSENGER.
BUT OUR SHIP IS DESIGNED
TO HAUL CARGO, NOT PEOPLE,
AND IT'S A VERY LONG JOURNEY.
PUTTING HER
IN SUSPENDED ANIMATION
WAS OUR ONLY CHOICE.
ALIEN: WE HAVE ANOTHER FIVE
MONTHS AHEAD OF US.
IF SHE WAKES UP,
THERE WON'T BE ENOUGH
FOOD, AIR TO BREATHE.
IF WE'RE FORCED TO
ABORT THE MISSION,
WE WON'T GET...PAID.
COMMANDER TUCKER
IS RESOURCEFUL.
I'M SURE HE'LL BE ABLE
TO ASSIST YOU.
TRIP: MIND IF I HAVE A LOOK?
PLEASE.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY ACCOMMODATING.
IF IT'S NOT TOO MUCH TROUBLE,
I'D LIKE TO MAKE
ANOTHER REQUEST.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE WE'VE ENJOYED
THE LUXURY...
OF A BATH.
OH. I UNDERSTAND.
T'POL WILL SHOW YOU
TO GUEST QUARTERS.
WHEN YOU'RE DONE,
I'LL HAVE MY CHEF
PREPARE YOU A MEAL.
ALIEN: THIS REGULATES POWER FLOW
TO THE BIO-POD.
LOOKS VERY CREATIVE.
THESE RELAYS ARE FROM
AN OLD ARDANAN SHUTTLE.
THEY WEREN'T DESIGNED TO
CARRY THIS MUCH CURRENT.
I'VE GOT SOME E.P.S. CONDUITS
THAT MIGHT DO THE TRICK.
TRIP: THIS'D BE A LOT EASIER
IF I COULD READ YOUR LANGUAGE.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'D LIKE TO ASK
OUR COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER
TO GIVE ME A HAND.
ALIEN: BY ALL MEANS.
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
NO.
NO, NO PROBLEM.
I'M GOING TO NEED SOME TOOLS
FROM ENTERPRISE.
WITH A LITTLE LUCK,
"SLEEPING BEAUTY" HERE WILL
NEVER KNOW THERE WAS A PROBLEM.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I HOPE I DIDN'T DEPLETE
YOUR WATER SUPPLY.
I'M SURE WE'LL MANAGE.
PLEASE.
T'POL TELLS ME YOUR VESSEL
CAN'T DO MUCH BETTER
THAN WARP 2.
WARP 2.2.
I'VE BEEN MAKING
SOME CALCULATIONS.
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
AT WARP 4.5,
ENTERPRISE CAN HAVE YOU
AT YOUR DESTINATION
IN LESS THAN FOUR DAYS.
THAT'S A GENEROUS OFFER,
BUT I'VE ALREADY
INCONVENIENCED YOU FAR TOO MUCH.
IT'S NO INCONVENIENCE.
WE'RE OUT HERE
TO MEET NEW PEOPLE.
YOU'RE HEADING
TOWARD AN INHABITED WORLD
WE'VE NEVER SEEN.
FIRST CONTACTS TEND TO GO
MORE SMOOTHLY
WHEN A FAMILIAR FACE
IS MAKING THE INTRODUCTIONS.
I'M SURE YOU'LL DO FINE
ON YOUR OWN.
YOU COULD DOCK
IN OUR LAUNCH BAY.
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT THAT STASIS POD.
WE HAVE PLENTY OF ROOM
FOR YOU AND YOUR PASSENGER.
IT'S NOT THAT SIMPLE, CAPTAIN.
THIS HAS ALL BEEN
CAREFULLY PREARRANGED.
HER FAMILY IS NOT EXPECTING HER
FOR ANOTHER FIVE MONTHS.
THEY'RE NOT EVEN ON HER
HOME WORLD AT THE MOMENT.
BUT I WILL ACCEPT YOUR OFFER
OF A MEAL...
IF IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
COMMANDER?
HELLO?
IS THAT
THE TRANSLATION?
GIVE OR TAKE AN ADVERB.
THANKS.
AT LEAST YOU DON'T HAVE
TO WORK ALONE.
HELL OF A WAY
TO TRAVEL, ISN'T IT?
WHO IS SHE? ANY IDEA?
I ASKED PLINN,
BUT HE DOESN'T SEEM TO
KNOW TOO MUCH ABOUT HER.
SAID SOMETHING ABOUT
STUDYING MEDICINE
AT A RESEARCH COLONY.
HOSHI: A DOCTOR?
TRIP: I SUPPOSE SO.
SHE MUST HAVE
A REAL PASSION FOR IT
IF SHE'S WILLING TO
GO THROUGH ALL THIS.
SHAME WE'LL NEVER
GET TO MEET HER.
IT'S NOT POLITE TO STARE,
COMMANDER.
WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED
TO MEAN?
LET ME KNOW
IF YOU HAVE ANY PROBLEMS
WITH THAT TRANSLATION.
I WASN'T STARING.
[ THUMPING ]
HOSHI?
[ THUMPING CONTINUES ]
[ MUFFLED SCREAMING ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[ SHOUTING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER: PROBLEM?
ALIEN: THE STASIS POD.
T'POL: WHAT ABOUT IT?
ALIEN: IT'S MALFUNCTIONING.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
CAPTAIN.
T'POL: I'LL SHOW YOU TO
THE DOCKING PORT.
ALIEN: I KNOW THE WAY.
[ MUFFLED SCREAMING ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
HELP ME OPEN THIS THING!
WE CAN'T BRING HER
OUT OF STASIS.
TRIP: SHE'S SUFFOCATING!
THE RELEASE IS JAMMED!
DON'T BOTHER!
WOMAN: [ GASPING, SCREAMING ]
TRIP: I'M SORRY ABOUT THIS,
BUT THE 02 RECYCLER
WENT OFF-LINE.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
YOU'RE GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
[ BEEPING ]
YES?
ALIEN: THERE'S A MINOR PROBLEM.
I'M GOING TO NEED
YOUR ASSISTANCE.
WHAT KIND OF PROBLEM?
ALIEN: THE MALFUNCTION
IS MORE COMPLICATED
THAN I EXPECTED.
I'LL BE THERE IN A MOMENT.
I DON'T MEAN TO BE RUDE.
ARCHER: NOT AT ALL.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
TRIP, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
ARCHER TO LIEUTENANT REED.
MR. PLINN?
THAT'S RIGHT.
LIEUTENANT REED.
THE CAPTAIN ASKED ME
TO ESCORT YOU BACK
TO YOUR SHIP.
PLINN: THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY.
I'M AFRAID I'M UNDER ORDERS.
HAVE I DONE SOMETHING WRONG?
IT'S JUST A PRECAUTION.
I NEVER REALIZED
LEAVING THE CAPTAIN'S TABLE
WOULD CAUSE SO MUCH CONCERN.
HE'S TRYING TO BREAK LOOSE.
SECURE THE DOCKING CLAMPS.
REPORT.
HE HASN'T GOTTEN FAR
AT WARP 2, SIR.
HAIL HIM.
HOSHI: NO RESPONSE.
PHASE CANNONS.
TARGET HIS ENGINES.
DIRECT HIT TO THE PORT NACELLE.
HE'S DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
BRING US INTO GRAPPLING RANGE.
HAIL HIM AGAIN.
TRAVIS: CAPTAIN.
T'POL?
DILITHIUM HYDROXYLS...
IONIZED PYROSULFATES.
TRAVIS: HE'S MOVING OFF.
STAY WITH HIM.
I THOUGHT YOU TOOK OUT
ONE OF HIS NACELLES?
SO DID I.
TRAVIS: OUR WARP DRIVE
WON'T ENGAGE.
REED: THAT CLOUD HE RELEASED,
IT GOT INTO THE PLASMA VENTS.
THEY'LL HAVE TO BE PURGED.
TRAVIS: HE'S MOVING
OUT OF SENSOR RANGE.
I'VE LOST HIM.
[ GROANS ]
[ THUNK ]
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
OH, WHAT THE HELL
DID YOU DO THAT FOR?
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
I'M NOT WORKING WITH THEM.
CALM DOWN.
I'M NOT GOING TO HURT YOU.
I'M -- I'M FROM A STARSHIP...
CALLED ENTERPRISE.
UH... ENTERPRISE.
NOW...
PUT THAT THING DOWN
AND I'LL UNTIE YOU.
YOUR HANDS...
I'LL FREE YOUR HANDS.
LET ME HELP YOU.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON?
ALIEN: IS IT REPAIRED?
WHAT?
ALIEN: THE STASIS POD.
WHERE'S CAPTAIN ARCHER?
YOUR SHIP
IS A LONG WAY FROM HERE.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
REPAIR THE POD SO WE CAN
PUT HER BACK IN STASIS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A FEW HOURS.
WORK QUICKLY.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
UH...YOU'RE WELCOME?
HAVE YOU SEEN A-A LITTLE DEVICE?
UM, IT'S ABOUT THIS BIG.
IT HAS A-A KEYPAD ON IT.
UM...IT'S
MY UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR.
IT'LL HELP US UNDERSTAND
EACH OTHER.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
THAT'S IT!
IT'S -- IT'S JUST
SO WE CAN TALK.
I NEED YOU TO SAY SOMETHING.
YOU GOT TO KEEP TALKING.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
[ TRANSLATOR BEEPING ]
A LITTLE MORE.
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
CAN YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
WHERE'S HOSHI
WHEN YOU NEED HER?
WHO IS HOSHI?!
THAT'S BETTER.
WOULD YOU MIND TELLING ME
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
HOW LONG HAVE
I BEEN IN STASIS?
WELL, YOU'D HAVE TO ASK THEM.
COMMANDER TUCKER TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, DO YOU HEAR ME?
YOU ARE AN OFFICER?
CHIEF ENGINEER.
FEELS LIKE WE'VE GONE TO WARP.
EXPLAIN YOURSELF.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT MY ABDUCTORS?
WE THOUGHT
THEY WERE CARGO PILOTS.
THEY CLAIMED
YOU WERE THEIR PASSENGER.
I AM THEIR PRISONER.
I WAS RETURNING
FROM A DIPLOMATIC MISSION
WHEN THEY ATTACKED
MY TRANSPORT...
MURDERED MY GUARDS.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHO I AM, DO YOU?
SHOULD I?
MY FAMILY IS KNOWN
ON HUNDREDS OF WORLDS.
WELL, I'M AFRAID
EARTH ISN'T ONE OF THEM.
SO, I TAKE IT
YOU'RE NOT A DOCTOR.
I AM FIRST MONARCH
OF THE SOVEREIGN DYNASTY
OF KRIOS PRIME.
OH.
CHARLES TUCKER III.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
SO, WHAT DO THESE GUYS WANT?
RANSOM.
NO DOUBT THEY'LL DEMAND
A HIGH PRICE FOR MY SAFE RETURN.
LISTEN, MY CAPTAIN
WILL BE LOOKING FOR ME.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO
IS GET OFF THIS SHIP
AND LET HIM KNOW
WHERE WE ARE.
AND HOW DO YOU PROPOSE
WE DO THAT?
I SAW A SHUTTLE BAY EARLIER.
THERE WERE
A COUPLE OF ESCAPE PODS.
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
WE'LL REMAIN HERE UNTIL THEY
CONTACT THE SOVEREIGN GUARD.
ONCE THE RANSOM HAS BEEN PAID,
WE'LL BE RELEASED.
WELL, IF IT'S ALL
THE SAME TO YOU,
I'D RATHER TAKE
MY CHANCES IN OPEN SPACE.
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
IF YOU LEAVE,
IT WOULD PROVOKE THEM.
IF I REMEMBER RIGHT,
THIS ACCESS TUBE LEADS TO
A JUNCTION NEAR THE SHUTTLE BAY.
YOU ARE NOT TO LEAVE
THIS CHAMBER.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
I'M NOT ONE OF YOUR SUBJECTS.
HE'S YOUR PARTNER.
YOU MUST HAVE SOME IDEA
WHERE HE'S GOING.
OBVIOUSLY,
I'M HIS VICTIM, AS WELL.
WHY ELSE WOULD
HE LEAVE ME HERE?
WHERE WERE YOU TAKING
YOUR PASSENGER?
GOFF HAD THE COORDINATES.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT SYSTEM
YOU WERE HEADING FOR?
IT WASN'T MY RESPONSIBILITY.
HE WAS PILOTING
THE SHIP, NOT ME.
I SPENT MOST OF MY TIME
LOOKING AFTER THE CARGO.
BELIEVE ME, CAPTAIN,
I'M AS EAGER TO FIND
MY PARTNER AS YOU ARE.
IF THAT'S TRUE...
THEN WE COULD
WORK TOGETHER
TO TRACK HIM DOWN.
I DON'T SEE HOW.
WE'VE GOT PRETTY GOOD
LONG-RANGE SENSORS,
BUT YOUR SHIP
COULD BE ANYWHERE
WITHIN A HALF DOZEN
LIGHT-YEARS.
IT'D BE A LOT EASIER
IF WE KNEW YOUR WARP FREQUENCY.
WELL, I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T HELP YOU WITH THAT.
I KNOW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT WARP ENGINES.
TAKE HIM BACK
TO DOCKING PORT 2.
PUT HIM IN THE AIRLOCK
AND POST A SECURITY DETAIL.
I'M TELLING YOU THE TRUTH!
WE'LL KEEP
THE OUTER HATCH UNLOCKED.
IF YOU DECIDE TO LEAVE,
YOU KNOW THE WAY OUT.
COULD YOU HAND ME
THAT CIRCUIT PROBE?
THE ONE WITH THE GREEN HANDLE?
YOU MUST BE ONE
HELL OF A DIPLOMAT.
IS YOUR ENTIRE SPECIES
SO ILL-MANNERED?
NO...JUST ME.
YOU KNOW, IF YOU WERE
THINKING RATIONALLY,
YOU'D BE REPAIRING
THAT STASIS POD.
HE DID THREATEN TO KILL YOU.
THAT'S PRECISELY WHY
I'M GETTING OUT OF HERE.
I REALLY DOUBT
THEY'RE GOING TO KEEP ME AROUND
ONCE I FIX THEIR PROBLEM.
YOU KNOW, I REALIZE
SOMEONE IN YOUR POSITION
ISN'T USED TO TAKING ADVICE
FROM A GUY LIKE ME...
BUT I STRONGLY SUGGEST
YOU COME ALONG.
HE'D NEVER HARM ME.
I'M TOO VALUABLE TO THEM.
I'VE BEEN INVOLVED
IN A FEW HOSTAGE SITUATIONS.
THEY RARELY TURN OUT
THE WAY YOU EXPECT.
YOU'RE CORRECT, MR. TUCKER.
I DON'T TAKE ADVICE
FROM PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
[ POP ]
YOU KNOW...
THAT STASIS POD
WON'T FIX ITSELF.
CHANCES ARE YOU'RE GOING TO
SPEND THE NEXT FIVE MONTHS
TIED UP IN THIS GRIMY
LITTLE CARGO HOLD.
NOT EXACTLY MY IDEA
OF A ROYAL VOYAGE.
I'LL BE FINE.
WHEN I GET BACK TO ENTERPRISE,
I'LL MAKE SURE WE GET
A MESSAGE TO YOUR HOME WORLD.
PRIOS...?
KRIOS PRIME.
TAKE CARE.
WOMAN: ONCE YOU'VE LAUNCHED
AN ESCAPE POD,
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THEY WON'T DESTROY IT?
I'M GOING TO REROUTE
THEIR INTERNAL SENSORS.
I'LL BE A MILLION KILOMETERS
AWAY BEFORE THEY KNOW
I'M GONE.
I'M MUCH BETTER COMPANY.
HOW MUCH FURTHER?
JUST A FEW MORE METERS.
ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS THE RIGHT DIRECTION?
KEEP YOUR VOICE DOWN.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO CALL YOU,
ANYWAY?
FIRST MONARCH?
YOUR HIGHNESS?
KAITAAMA.
WHAT IS THAT,
SOME KIND OF A TITLE?
IT'S MY NAME.
OH.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THESE LEAD TO INTERNAL SENSORS.
WE DON'T HAVE ALL DAY.
THIS IS MEANT FOR ONE PERSON.
WE'LL HAVE TO MAKE DO.
UNLESS YOU KNOW HOW TO FLY
ONE OF THESE THINGS.
[ GROANS ]
WHAT WAS THAT?
WE'RE CROSSING
THE SUBSPACE THRESHOLD.
[ SIGHS ]
THAT WASN'T SO BAD.
KAITAAMA: WHAT DO YOU
PROPOSE WE DO NEXT?
TO BE HONEST, I HADN'T
REALLY THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
I ASSUMED YOU HAD A PLAN.
I WAS ONLY JOKING.
THEY DO HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR
WHERE YOU COME FROM?
AMONG THE COMMONERS.
ONLY JOKING.
UNH...
IT'S ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THEY REALIZE WE'RE GONE.
NO DOUBT THEY'LL COME
ABOUT AND LOOK FOR US.
WE NEED A PLACE TO HIDE.
WHERE?
IF I'M TRANSLATING THIS RIGHT,
THERE'S A SYSTEM ABOUT
90 MILLION KILOMETERS FROM HERE.
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO
REACH IT IN A DAY OR SO.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
ANY OF THOSE PLANETS
ARE HABITABLE?
ONLY ONE WAY TO FIND OUT.
PERMISSION TO SET A COURSE,
YOUR SOVEREIGNTY?
PROCEED.
TRIP: THIS WOULD BE
A WHOLE LOT EASIER
IF YOU'D STOP
MOVING AROUND.
YOU'RE TOUCHING ME.
I'M AFRAID
I DON'T HAVE MUCH CHOICE.
IT'S INAPPROPRIATE
TO TOUCH THE FIRST MONARCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME TO STEP OUTSIDE
UNTIL I'M DONE.
EXCUSE ME.
THERE WE GO.
LANDING THRUSTERS...
OH, NO, WAIT,
THEY'RE STABILIZERS.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA HOW
TO CONTROL THIS VEHICLE.
I'M WORKING ON IT.
EVEN IF WE DO FIND
A BREATHABLE ATMOSPHERE
AND YOU MANAGE TO LAND
WITHOUT KILLING US,
WHAT WILL WE DO ABOUT FOOD?
WATER?
THERE COULD BE HOSTILE
LIFE-FORMS ON THE SURFACE.
HOW WILL WE PROTECT
OURSELVES?
LOOK, I'VE GOT LESS
THAN 24 HOURS
TO FIGURE OUT HOW
TO SCAN A STAR SYSTEM
AND PROGRAM
A DESCENT SEQUENCE
IN A LANGUAGE
I DON'T UNDERSTAND,
AND I'M NOT GOING
TO GET IT DONE
WITH YOU INTERRUPTING ME
EVERY FIVE SECONDS.
SO, I'D APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU'D KEEP QUIET
UNTIL I'M FINISHED.
NOW, LIFT YOUR BUTT.
MY WHAT?
YOUR BEHIND --
YOUR REAR END.
I HAVEN'T CHECKED
THAT PANEL YET.
QUICKLY.
YOU KNOW, YOU WERE
A LOT MORE PLEASANT
IN STASIS.
I THINK I FOUND
THE LANDING THRUSTERS.
I UNDERSTAND HOW DIFFICULT
THIS MUST BE FOR SOMEONE
OF YOUR UPBRINGING.
BUT WE COULD BE STUCK
OUT HERE FOR A WHILE.
WE SHOULD FIND A WAY
TO GET ALONG.
I'M WILLING TO GIVE
IT A TRY IF YOU ARE.
MY HAND.
YOU'RE SITTING ON MY HAND.
I'LL TRY.
REED: THE PRISONER, SIR...
AS ORDERED.
ARCHER: THANK YOU.
REED: WILL THERE BE
ANYTHING ELSE, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: NOT RIGHT NOW,
LIEUTENANT.
DISMISSED.
HAVE A SEAT.
WHY HAVE I BEEN BROUGHT HERE?
SIT DOWN.
I ALREADY TOLD YOU
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
WE'RE NOT HERE TO TALK
ABOUT YOUR PARTNER.
WE'RE HERE TO TALK ABOUT YOU.
WHAT ABOUT ME?
YOU'RE FACING SOME
VERY SERIOUS CHARGES, MR. PLINN.
WHERE WE COME FROM,
CRIMINALS ARE HELD
ACCOUNTABLE
FOR THEIR ACTIONS.
IF THEY'RE FOUND GUILTY,
THEY'RE PUNISHED.
THIS IS WHERE YOUR TRIBUNAL
IS GOING TO TAKE PLACE.
TRIBUNAL?
I AM NOT SUBJECT TO YOUR LAWS.
THAT'S NOT FOR ME TO DECIDE.
STARFLEET ASKED
THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
TO ASSIGN A JUDICIAL
ADMINISTRATOR TO ENTERPRISE.
SOMEONE WHO WOULDN'T BE SWAYED
BY HUMAN EMOTION --
SOMEONE OBJECTIVE, LOGICAL.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
SUBCOMMANDER T'POL
HAS ALREADY REVIEWED
THE EVIDENCE.
THIS TRIBUNAL...
IS NOTHING MORE
THAN A FORMALITY.
I THOUGHT
YOU SHOULD BE PREPARED.
HER PUNISHMENTS CAN BE...
SEVERE.
HOW SEVERE?
IF YOU'RE LATE FOR YOUR SHIFT,
YOU MIGHT RECEIVE A BEATING.
BUT FOR MORE
GRIEVOUS OFFENSES...
DERELICTION OF DUTY,
CONDUCT UNBECOMING AN OFFICER...
[ SIGHS ]
WE STARTED OUT
WITH 83 CREWMEN ON BOARD.
WE'RE DOWN TO 76.
BUT I HAVEN'T DONE
ANYTHING WRONG!
ARCHER: ACCESSORY
TO KIDNAPPING,
RESISTING ARREST,
OBSTRUCTION OF AN INVESTIGATION,
CAUSING DAMAGE
TO A STARFLEET VESSEL...
WHAT DAMAGE?
WHEN YOUR PARTNER FLED,
HE RELEASED A CLOUD
OF DILITHIUM HYDROXYLS
THAT CLOGGED OUR PLASMA VENTS.
I HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THAT.
AS I SAID...
I'M NOT THE ONE
YOU HAVE TO CONVINCE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
SUBCOMMANDER.
T'POL: HAS THE ACCUSED
BEEN INFORMED OF THE CHARGES?
ARCHER: YES, MA'AM.
HOW MUCH DO YOU WEIGH?
WHAT?
YOUR WEIGHT.
72 KILOGRAMS.
HEIGHT?
1.8 METERS.
WHY ARE YOU ASKING
THESE QUESTIONS?
DOES YOUR CULTURE OBSERVE
ANY POSTMORTEM RITUALS?
THIS IS NOT FAIR!
I DEMAND TO SPEAK WITH
SOMEONE FROM MY GOVERNMENT!
HE'S GOT A POINT.
WE'VE NEVER TRIED
AN ALIEN BEFORE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD CONTACT
THE HIGH COMMAND.
THEY'VE GRANTED ME COMPLETE
AUTONOMY IN THESE MATTERS.
IF I HAD TO CONSULT
MY SUPERIORS
EVERY TIME I MADE A RULING,
IT WOULD DEFEAT MY PURPOSE HERE.
WE'LL CONVENE AT 1800 HOURS.
ARCHER: AS YOU WISH.
YOU CAN'T ALLOW THIS.
THERE'S NOTHING I CAN DO.
BUT YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN!
[ SIGHS ]
SHE OWES ME A FEW FAVORS.
I CAN'T PROMISE ANYTHING,
BUT I...
I'D BE WILLING
TO ASK FOR LENIENCY.
OF COURSE, I'D WANT
SOMETHING IN RETURN.
WE STILL HAVEN'T FOUND
A WAY TO LOCATE YOUR VESSEL.
IF YOU COULD REMEMBER
THAT WARP FREQUENCY...?
ARE THERE ANY PROVISIONS?
I'M HUNGRY.
YOU MIGHT CHECK THAT
STORAGE COMPARTMENT
ABOVE YOUR HEAD.
YOU DO IT.
I'M BUSY.
[ RATTLING ]
IF YOU FIND
ANY WATER UP THERE,
I COULD USE SOME.
THANKS.
ALLOW ME.
I'M NOT CONTAGIOUS.
IS IT EDIBLE?
WELL, DEPENDS
HOW HUNGRY YOU ARE.
REMINDS ME OF MY FIRST CAR.
CAR?
A FOUR-WHEELED VEHICLE.
WASN'T MUCH BIGGER THAN THIS.
ALL WE'RE MISSING
IS THE OCEAN BREEZE
COMING OFF THE GULF.
I USED TO DRIVE OUT
TO A PLACE CALLED
CHATKIN POINT...
PARK ALONG THE SHORELINE
AND STARE AT THE MOON
WITH MY GIRLFRIEND.
DON'T WORRY.
I WON'T MAKE A PASS AT YOU.
THE SOVEREIGN GUARD WOULD
CUT OFF ONE OF YOUR HANDS.
YOU MUST BE A FUN DATE.
THE FIRST MONARCH DOESN'T
SOCIALIZE WITH THE OPPOSITE SEX.
YOU'VE NEVER BEEN ON A DATE?
FOUR YEARS AGO,
BEFORE I WAS SELECTED
TO ASCEND TO FIRST MONARCH,
I WAS COURTED BY YOUNG MEN
FROM MANY NOBLE FAMILIES.
NOW I SPEND MY PERSONAL TIME
IN THE COMPANY
OF MY FATHER'S ADVISORS.
SOUNDS KIND OF LONELY.
YOU HAVEN'T FINISHED YOUR WORK.
IT'S ALL WATER.
THERE'S A CHAIN OF ISLANDS
NEAR THE EQUATOR.
WILL WE BE ABLE TO BREATHE?
OXYGEN, NITROGEN,
A TRACE OF METHANE.
NOTHING WE CAN'T HANDLE.
DO YOU DETECT ANY LIFE-FORMS?
IF I COULD FIGURE OUT
HOW TO USE THE BIO-SENSORS.
ARE YOU CERTAIN WE HAVE
THE CORRECT PLANET?
IT'S THE ONLY ONE
WITH AN ATMOSPHERE.
YOU MAY BEGIN OUR DESCENT.
LET'S HOPE I GET THIS RIGHT.
WE'RE ENTERING THE THERMOSPHERE.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
THE PORT STABILIZER'S DOWN.
CAN YOU REPAIR IT?
NO, BUT THE STARBOARD ONE
SHOULD KEEP US ON COURSE.
MR. TUCKER!
SO FAR SO GOOD.
8,000 METERS.
I THINK THEY'RE METERS.
7,000.
I'M PRETTY SURE
THE BRAKING THRUSTERS
ARE FIRING.
5,000 METERS.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO GRAB HOLD
OF SOMETHING.
2,000 METERS.
1,000...
HOLD ON.
[ CRASH ]
[ HISSING ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT IS THAT?
DAMNED IF I KNOW.
[ GROANS ]
[ BIRDS CALLING,
INSECTS BUZZING ]
KAITAAMA:
THIS HEAT IS UNBEARABLE.
TRIP: IT'S NOTHING COMPARED
TO A SUMMER
IN THE EVERGLADES.
AT LEAST THERE AREN'T
ANY MOSQUITOES.
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
OVER THERE.
LOOKS LIKE A GOOD PLACE
TO SET UP CAMP.
YOUR VESSEL WILL NEVER
FIND US HERE.
DON'T UNDERESTIMATE
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
YOU'RE BLEEDING.
IT'S JUST A SCRATCH.
REMOVE YOUR UNIFORM.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT LATER.
WE HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT MICROBES LIVE
IN THIS ENVIRONMENT.
IT COULD BECOME INFECTED.
I SAID LATER!
YOU'RE MY ONLY HOPE
OF SURVIVING HERE, MR. TUCKER.
I DON'T INTEND TO LET YOU DIE.
[ SIGHS ]
THIS ONE.
HOLD STILL.
THE PROVISIONS WON'T LAST
FOR MORE THAN A DAY.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THERE'S
PLENTY OF WILDLIFE.
I GREW UP IN A PLACE
KIND OF LIKE THIS.
I DON'T THINK
WE'RE GOING TO STARVE.
AND I CAN USE THE THRUSTER
ASSEMBLY FROM THE POD
TO START A FIRE,
BOIL SOME WATER.
THANKS.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE BEST YOU COULD DO?
THERE'S VERY LITTLE DRY WOOD.
KEEP LOOKING.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
I'M NOT YOUR SERVANT.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO WAS RAISED
IN A PRIMITIVE ENVIRONMENT.
YOU FIND THE WOOD.
WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY BETTER SUITED
TO PHYSICAL LABOR.
IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
WE'RE NOT IN A PALACE.
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF.
YOU WON'T SURVIVE
WITHOUT MY HELP,
SO IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT I'M THE ONE IN CHARGE.
THE KING OF THE SWAMP!
NOW GET YOUR ASS OUT THERE
AND DON'T COME BACK
WITHOUT AN ARMFUL OF DRY WOOD!
I SHOULD HAVE YOU IMPRISONED
FOR SPEAKING TO ME THAT WAY.
YOU SHOULD GIVE ME A MEDAL.
YOU'D BE DEAD
IF IT WEREN'T FOR ME!
I'M BEGINNING TO THINK
THAT WOULD BE PREFERABLE.
I DOUBT THE COMMONERS
BACK HOME WOULD COMPLAIN.
HOW DARE YOU!
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO TOOK A SWING AT ME!
YOU INSULTED
THE FIRST MONARCH!
I'M JUST A PETTY
COMMONER, REMEMBER?
RAISED ON A PRIMI--
[ BEEPING SOUND ]
[ BEEPING CONTINUES ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
A HOMING BEACON.
UNLESS I'M WAY OFF,
SOMEONE JUST LOCKED ON TO IT.
YOUR VESSEL?
NO WAY TO TELL.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROWLING ]
LEAVE HIM.
LET'S FIND HIS WEAPON.
THERE'S SOMEONE ELSE HERE.
ARCHER: TRIP?
THIS A BAD TIME?
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SEPTEMBER 12, 2152.
WE'VE RENDEZVOUSED
WITH A KRIOS BATTLE CRUISER,
WHICH HAS TAKEN THE KIDNAPPERS
INTO CUSTODY.
SO, WHEN DO YOU ASCEND?
246 DAYS.
IT'S A LONG SHOT,
BUT MAYBE ENTERPRISE
WILL GET THE CHANCE
TO VISIT KRIOS PRIME
BEFORE THEN.
OF COURSE, FROM WHAT
YOU'VE TOLD ME,
I DOUBT YOUR FAMILY
WOULD LET ME SEE YOU.
I DOUBT THEY WOULD.
BUT ONCE I'VE BEEN MADE
FIRST MONARCH,
I'LL HAVE THE AUTHORITY
TO CHANGE THE RULES.
WHAT KIND OF CHANGES?
COME VISIT ME.
PERHAPS YOU'LL FIND OUT.