ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SEPTEMBER 18, 2152.
WE'VE ENTERED ORBIT
OF AN UNINHABITED PLANET.
OUR SCANS SHOW IT'S TEEMING
WITH ALL SORTS OF PLANT
AND ANIMAL LIFE.
I'LL BE LEADING A SURVEY TEAM
TO THE SURFACE.
TUCKER: THERE'S A GORGE
ON THE SOUTHERN CONTINENT
FIVE TIMES DEEPER
THAN THE GRAND CANYON.
ARCHER: WHAT HAVE YOU
GOT IN MIND?
TUCKER: HOW ABOUT A LITTLE
RIVER RAFTING?
T'POL SAYS IT ONLY GETS
DARK FOUR DAYS A MONTH
BECAUSE OF THE BINARY SUNS.
WE'LL HAVE PLENTY
OF DAYLIGHT LEFT
AFTER WE'RE DONE
WORKING EVERY NIGHT.
ARCHER: IT'S GOING TO TAKE
AT LEAST A WEEK
TO COMPLETE THE SURVEY.
SHOULD BE ENOUGH TIME
TO SNEAK IN SOME R&amp;R.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
T'Pol: Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
T'Pol: We've got an alien vessel
approaching.
They're hailing us.
ARCHER: PUT THEM THROUGH
TO SHUTTLEPOD 1.
T'Pol: Yes, sir.
TUCKER: NEW PLANET,
NEW ALIENS...BANNER DAY.
WE'RE VERY RELIEVED
TO SEE YOU.
I'M RELLUS TAGRIM.
THIS IS MY CREW.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN ARCHER OF
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
SOMETHING WE CAN DO FOR YOU?
CONSIDERING
THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
WE WOULD LIKE PERMISSION
TO COME ABOARD
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
ARCHER: WHAT CIRCUMSTANCES?
THE NEUTRONIC WAVE FRONT...
IT'S ALMOST HERE.
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
TUCKER: NOTHING ON SENSORS.
TAGRIM: YOU SHOULD DETECT
THE STORM IN A FEW MINUTES.
IT'S TRAVELING AT HIGH WARP.
ONCE WE'RE ABOARD,
I SUGGEST THAT YOU GO
TO WARP 7 IMMEDIATELY.
ARCHER: OUR TOP SPEED IS WARP 5.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
T'POL: THE WAVE FRONT SPANS MORE
THAN HALF A DOZEN LIGHT YEARS.
A VULCAN STARSHIP
ENCOUNTERED A CLASS-5
OVER A CENTURY AGO.
THE VESSEL WAS...
NEARLY DESTROYED.
ARCHER: HOW LONG UNTIL IT HITS?
T'POL: APPROXIMATELY FOUR HOURS.
REED: IF WE REINFORCE
STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO WEATHER IT
WITHOUT TOO MUCH TROUBLE.
PHLOX: ENTERPRISE MAY SURVIVE.
THE CREW IS ANOTHER MATTER.
THE STORM IS SATURATED
WITH RADIOLYTIC ISOTOPES.
IF THE CREW IS EXPOSED,
THEY'LL BE DEAD
WITHIN THREE MINUTES.
SICKBAY IS THE MOST
HEAVILY SHIELDED SECTION.
IT'S POSSIBLE THAT SOME
OF THE CREW COULD SURVIVE THERE.
ARCHER: WE CAN'T FIT 83 PEOPLE
INTO SICKBAY,
AND I'M NOT ABOUT TO DRAW LOTS.
WHAT ABOUT THE CATWALK?
YOU KNOW,
THE MAINTENANCE SHAFT
RUNNING THE LENGTH
OF EACH NACELLE.
ARCHER: THEY ARE
HEAVILY SHIELDED...
SOME KIND OF OSMIUM ALLOY,
IF I REMEMBER.
YOU'RE PROPOSING WE TAKE REFUGE
IN A CRAWLSPACE?
IT'LL BE A TIGHT SQUEEZE,
BUT THERE'S NO REASON
WE CAN'T FIT 83 PEOPLE IN THERE,
AND WHATEVER SUPPLIES WE NEED.
DOCTOR?
PHLOX: DO YOU KNOW THE
ABSORPTION DEPTH OF THIS ALLOY?
AT LEAST 20,000 PARTICLES
PER MICRON.
PHLOX: IT SHOULD BE ADEQUATE.
TUCKER: THERE'S JUST
ONE OTHER PROBLEM.
IT GETS KIND OF TOASTY IN THERE
WHEN THE WARP COILS
ARE ON LINE...
ABOUT 300 DEGREES.
WE'D HAVE TO SHUT DOWN
THE MAIN REACTOR.
ARCHER: I DON'T SEE
THAT WE HAVE ANY CHOICE.
WE'LL USE THE CATWALK.
AND SET UP A COMMAND STATION
IN ONE OF THE COMPARTMENTS.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: YOU'LL BE IN CHARGE
OF THE EVACUATION.
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT, TRAVIS.
MAYWEATHER: MAYBE WE SHOULD
OPEN A WINDOW.
TUCKER: YOU THINK
IT'S STUFFY NOW,
WAIT TILL WE GET 83 PEOPLE
IN HERE.
MAYWEATHER: DON'T FORGET PORTHOS
AND ALL THE DOCTOR'S ANIMALS.
YOU EVER BEEN THROUGH A STORM
AS BAD AS THIS?
MAYWEATHER: WE RAN INTO
A CLASS-3 ONCE,
HAD TO TAKE SHELTER
IN THE SHIP'S CORE.
WE WERE DOWN THERE
FOR SIX WEEKS.
TUCKER: SIX WEEKS?
MAYWEATHER: ANY IDEA
ABOUT A LATRINE?
TUCKER: OH, I NEVER THOUGHT
ABOUT THAT.
THERE ARE SOME STORAGE LOCKERS
IN THE AFT COMPARTMENT.
WE OUGHT TO BE ABLE TO
CONVERT A COUPLE OF THEM.
TUCKER: THIS'LL BE OUR BRIDGE.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO JURY-RIG THESE PANELS,
TAP THEM INTO COMMAND FUNCTIONS.
MAYWEATHER: NOT MUCH ROOM
FOR A CAPTAIN'S CHAIR.
THAT STORM
MUST'VE BEEN PRETTY SCARY.
WE ONLY GOT WORRIED
WHEN THE GENERATORS WENT DOWN.
WE LOST THE GRAV-PLATING,
LIFE SUPPORT...
I'LL NEVER FORGET THAT LOOK
IN MY FATHER'S EYES.
HE KNEW WE WERE IN TROUBLE.
[ SNIFFS ]
ARCHER: SORRY TO KEEP YOU
IN THERE SO LONG.
PLEASE.
WE UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: MY SCIENCE OFFICER
TELLS ME
YOU'RE FROM THE TAKRET SYSTEM.
THAT'S A LONG WAY FROM HERE.
TAGRIM: OUR WORK OFTEN
TAKES US FAR FROM HOME.
TAKRETI: WE'RE STELLAR
CARTOGRAPHERS.
ARCHER: REALLY?
ONCE WE GET OUT OF THE STORM,
MAYBE YOU COULD HELP US
UPDATE OUR STAR CHARTS.
TAGRIM: WE'D BE PLEASED.
PHLOX: THIS WAY.
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
T'POL: YOU'RE BEHIND SCHEDULE.
DO YOU NEED HELP?
PHLOX: I UNDERSTAND YOU'VE
ALLOTTED 15 CUBIC METERS
FOR MEDICAL SUPPLIES?
T'POL: THAT'S CORRECT.
THAT MEANS
THERE'S ONLY ENOUGH ROOM
FOR TWO THIRDS OF THESE CAGES.
[ T'POL INHALES ]
T'POL: PERHAPS SOME OF
YOUR CREATURES COULD SHARE.
PHLOX: THEY'LL EAT EACH OTHER.
THEY'RE VITAL TO MY WORK
AND THE HEALTH OF THIS CREW.
I'M NOT ACCUSTOMED
TO MAKING EMOTIONAL APPEALS.
PLEASE...DON'T ASK ME
TO CHOOSE BETWEEN THEM.
T'POL: ALL RIGHT.
20 CUBIC METERS.
MY EDOSIAN SLUGS THANK YOU.
TUCKER: I'M--I'M AFRAID
THESE AREN'T
FIRST-CLASS ACCOMMODATIONS.
TAGRIM: THEY'LL BE FINE,
COMMANDER.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
FOR YOUR HOSPITALITY.
TUCKER: WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
A LOT OF TIME
TO GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
IF YOU NEED ANYTHING,
I'LL BE RIGHT OVER HERE.
TAKRETI: I DON'T KNOW THE FIRST
THING ABOUT STELLAR CARTOGRAPHY.
TAGRIM: GURI--
GURI: WHAT IF THEY BEGIN
TO ASK QUESTIONS?
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I DIDN'T EXPECT IT
TO BE BEAUTIFUL.
ARCHER: TOO BAD WE DON'T
HAVE TIME TO RUN SOME SCANS.
T'POL: WE'LL BE
INSIDE THE PHENOMENON
FOR NEARLY EIGHT DAYS.
WE CAN RUN ALL
THE SCANS WE WANT.
LIEUTENANT REED HAS COMPLETED
HIS MODIFICATIONS.
ARCHER: I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS
ABOUT SHUTTING DOWN
THE POWER GRID.
A SINGLE NEUTRONIC SURGE
COULD OVERLOAD THE GRID
AND DAMAGE CRITICAL SYSTEMS.
ARCHER: I DID A LITTLE RESEARCH
IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
THAT CLASS-5 STORM
A CENTURY AGO...
INVOLVED THE STARSHIP T'PLANA.
APPARENTLY, THEY COULDN'T
OUTRUN THE WAVE FRONT.
IT WAS LOST WITH ALL HANDS.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
IT WAS NEARLY DESTROYED.
I MUST HAVE REMEMBERED
INCORRECTLY.
BRIDGE TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
Tucker: Go ahead.
READY FOR THE HANDOFF?
GIVE ME A SECOND.
TUCKER: STANDING BY, CAPTAIN.
[ BEEPING ]
TUCKER: WE'RE IN
THE DRIVER'S SEAT.
SEE YOU IN A FEW MINUTES.
ARCHER OUT.
LET'S CLOSE UP SHOP.
ARCHER: YOU DONE A HEAD COUNT?
THE ENTIRE CREW'S ACCOUNTED FOR,
INCLUDING ONE QUADRUPED.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO TRY OUT
THE CAPTAIN'S CHAIR?
ARCHER: MAYBE LATER.
WHERE'S THE COM?
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ALL HANDS, THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
This catwalk is going
to be our home for a while--
a week, maybe more.
You may not be comfortable,
but you'll be alive.
We have the best crew in the
fleet and the sturdiest ship.
I promise you,
we'll get through this.
ARCHER: TIME?
ONE MINUTE, FIVE SECONDS.
POLARIZE THE HULL PLATING.
30 SECONDS.
[ RUMBLING ]
TRAVIS?
SPATIAL TURBULENCE.
20 SECONDS.
T'POL: 15.
10.
ALL HANDS, BRACE FOR IMPACT.
MAYWEATHER: AFT STABILIZERS
AREN'T ENGAGING.
TRY THEM AGAIN!
GRAV-SHEAR'S DROPPING.
THAT SHOULD BE
THE WORST OF IT, SIR...
AT LEAST FOR NOW.
ARCHER: YOURS?
LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE ALMOST FINISHED.
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
WHO WAS THE FIRST
VULCAN AMBASSADOR TO EARTH?
SIX LETTERS, ENDS WITH AN R?
SOLKAR...I THINK.
THANKS, CAPTAIN.
DON'T MENTION IT.
[ SIGHS ]
-HOW YOU HOLDING UP?
-PRETTY WELL, SIR.
A FEW DAYS IN THIS PLACE
SHOULD CURE ANYONE
OF CLAUSTROPHOBIA.
YOUR QUARTERS WILL PROBABLY FEEL
LIKE A BALLROOM AFTER THIS.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN.
CAN'T YOU ORDER THE STORM
TO CALM DOWN A LITTLE?
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
HOW ARE THEY DOING?
WELL, YOUR GUESS
IS AS GOOD AS MINE.
ONE OF THEM CAME OUT
A FEW HOURS AGO,
TOLD US WE WERE MAKING
TOO MUCH NOISE.
AND I'VE BEEN REAL FRIENDLY...
EVEN ASKED THEM
TO JOIN THE GAME.
DOESN'T SEEM LIKE THEY WANT
TO HAVE ANYTHING TO DO WITH US.
LET'S GIVE THEM
A LITTLE TIME TO ADJUST.
YOU KNOW, I BET BY NOW
WE'D HAVE SET UP CAMP
ON THE RIM OF THAT CANYON...
HAD A FIRE GOING.
THERE'LL BE OTHER CANYONS.
PHLOX: LIEUTENANT,
ARE YOU PASSING THROUGH,
OR IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN HELP YOU WITH?
REED: ACTUALLY,
THERE IS SOMETHING.
PHLOX: YES?
REED: AHEM.
I ASSUME I CAN DEPEND ON
DOCTOR-PATIENT CONFIDENTIALITY.
PHLOX: THIS WOULDN'T
HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH GASTROINTESTINAL
DISTRESS?
IS IT THAT OBVIOUS?
PHLOX: NOT AT ALL.
THERE'S A NOTATION
IN YOUR MEDICAL FILE,
SOMETHING ABOUT AN UNFORTUNATE
INCIDENT DURING ZERO-G TRAINING?
THE E.V. SIMULATOR AT LUNAPORT,
OR AS STARFLEET TRAINEES
CALL IT, THE VOMITORIUM.
PHLOX: NOTHING TO BE
EMBARRASSED ABOUT.
I'VE TREATED A NUMBER OF CREWMEN
THIS AFTERNOON
FOR MOTION SICKNESS.
THAT SHOULD LAST
FOR ABOUT 12 HOURS.
OH. THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
ARCHER: FEELING ALL RIGHT,
MALCOLM?
REED: UH...NEVER BETTER.
ANY PROBLEMS WITH THE CREW?
OH, A FEW BUMPS AND BRUISES
FROM THE TURBULENCE.
NOTHING TOO SERIOUS.
ARCHER: I COULD SEE ABOUT
MOVING SOME OF THIS
TO THE AFT SECTION.
NONSENSE!
I HAVE PLENTY OF ROOM.
I FIND THE CLOSE QUARTERS
RATHER COMFORTING.
IT REMINDS ME OF HOME.
I DIDN'T REALIZE SPACE
WAS AT A PREMIUM ON DENOBULA.
12 BILLION PEOPLE SHARING
ONE CONTINENT.
LET ME KNOW
IF YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND.
[ HATCH OPENS ]
TRAVIS?
MAYWEATHER: WE'VE GOT A CLUSTER
OF PLASMA EDDIES
ABOUT 80,000 KILOMETERS AHEAD.
I SHOULD BE ABLE
TO STEER CLEAR OF THEM.
ARCHER: WAKE ME
IF THERE'S A PROBLEM.
MAYWEATHER: AYE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WHEN WE'RE PAST
THOSE EDDIES,
TRY AND GET SOME REST YOURSELF.
ENSIGN TANNER CAN RELIEVE YOU.
THANK YOU, SIR.
-GOOD NIGHT.
-NIGHT.
ARCHER: HEY. HEY.
GO ON. GO TO SLEEP.
YEAH.
PHEW.
OH!
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
IS THIS BOTHERING YOU?
T'POL: ONLY SLIGHTLY.
[ PADD TURNS OFF ]
[ PADD BEEPING ]
AM I DISTURBING YOU?
ONLY SLIGHTLY.
ARCHER: YOU KNOW, THERE'S
A BRIGHT SIDE TO ALL OF THIS.
REALLY?
IT'S BRINGING THE CREW
CLOSER TOGETHER.
IF YOU FORGET
ABOUT THE STORM OUTSIDE,
THIS IS ALMOST LIKE GOING
ON A CAMPING TRIP.
PERHAPS WE CAN SING
A FEW SONGS LATER.
ARCHER: HAVEN'T YOU EVER
GONE CAMPING?
IN A MANNER OF SPEAKING.
I ONCE PARTICIPATED
IN THE KAHS-WAN RITUAL.
I WAS TAKEN TO THE DESERT
AND LEFT TO SURVIVE FOR 10 DAYS.
SOUNDS FUN.
YOU...HAVEN'T LEFT
THE COMMAND AREA MUCH TODAY.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO WANDER AROUND,
GET TO KNOW THE CREW.
I'M FAMILIAR
WITH EVERY ONE OF THEM.
THERE'S A LOT MORE TO THESE
PEOPLE THAN JUST THEIR NAMES.
IT'D BE GOOD FOR YOU
TO FRATERNIZE A LITTLE.
IS THAT AN ORDER?
DOES IT HAVE TO BE?
I'M NOT SKILLED
AT FRATERNIZING.
HERE'S A CHANCE TO LEARN.
REED: I'LL SEE YOUR STRAWBERRY
SHORTCAKE...
AND I'LL RAISE YOU
ONE PINEAPPLE COBBLER.
-BROCCOLI?
-I'M OUT OF DESSERTS.
MAYWEATHER: CALL.
OH, WHAT I WOULDN'T GIVE
FOR A SHOWER RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
WHEN THIS HAND'S OVER,
MAYBE YOU COULD LOOK
INTO BUILDING ONE.
WOULD YOU LIKE A SAUNA
WHILE I'M AT IT?
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU KNEW WE'D BE STUCK
IN HERE FOR OVER A WEEK.
YOU MIGHT'VE GIVEN A LITTLE
THOUGHT TO MAKING IT TOLERABLE.
I ONLY HAD FOUR HOURS, MALCOLM.
YOU'RE LUCKY WE'VE GOT A TOILET.
WELL, I OBVIOUSLY OVERESTIMATED
YOUR PEOPLE'S ABILITIES
WHEN IT COMES
TO INDOOR PLUMBING.
YOU WANT TO TAKE A SHOWER?
BUILD ONE YOURSELF.
-THANKS, CHEF.
REED: POT ROAST?
OH, COME ON.
THAT'S THE THIRD TIME
IN THREE DAYS!
AH!
MAYWEATHER: ANYONE KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE SHOWING TONIGHT?
"THE DAY THE EARTH STOOD STILL."
WE'RE HAVING MOVIE NIGHT
IN HERE?
CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
I SET UP A MONITOR
IN COMPARTMENT 5.
THE SCREEN'S
A LITTLE SMALL, BUT...
WHO'S PICKING THESE MOVIES?
SHOULDN'T WE ALL GET A VOTE?
I THINK SOMETHING'S BURNING.
TUCKER: ARE YOU AWARE
YOU'RE SITTING ON TOP OF
A PLASMA MANIFOLD?
YOU GOT TO TURN THAT THING OFF!
[ SIZZLING ]
TAGRIM: I APOLOGIZE, COMMANDER.
WE SHOULD'VE SPOKEN
WITH YOU FIRST.
TUCKER: THAT MIGHT'VE BEEN
A GOOD IDEA.
TAKRETI: WE'VE HAD TROUBLE
DIGESTING YOUR FOOD.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Archer: Archer to Tucker.
TUCKER: GO AHEAD.
Archer: I need you
in the command area right away.
TUCKER: I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
I'LL TALK TO CHEF.
MAYBE HE CAN...
HEAT THAT UP FOR YOU.
WE MAY HAVE A PROBLEM
IN ENGINEERING.
THE ANTIMATTER INJECTORS
HAVE COME ON LINE.
THAT CAN'T BE RIGHT.
PROBABLY JUST A GLITCH.
THINK YOU'VE GOT ROOM FOR ONE
MORE SLEEPING BAG IN HERE?
ARCHER: NOT HAPPY
WITH YOUR BUNKMATES?
I CAUGHT THEM
THROWING A BARBECUE
NEXT TO A PLASMA MANIFOLD.
NOW, I UNDERSTAND
WE'RE EXPLORERS--
WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND
ABOUT DIFFERENT CULTURES,
BUT THESE GUYS
ARE DRIVING ME CRAZY.
THEY ONLY NEED
TO SLEEP ONCE A WEEK.
SO THEY'VE KEPT US UP
THE LAST TWO NIGHTS
WITH THEIR STRANGE RITUALS--
CHANTING, WALKING IN CIRCLES.
THEY'VE PRACTICALLY TAKEN
OVER THE COMPARTMENT!
DON'T FORGET THEY'RE THE ONES
WHO WARNED US ABOUT THE STORM.
WE OWE THEM.
BE PATIENT.
I'M TRYING.
TUCKER: LOOKS LIKE
THE MATTER INJECTORS
AND THE ANTIMATTER INJECTORS
ARE ON LINE.
TWO SENSOR GLITCHES?
T'POL: A POWER SURGE COULD HAVE
TRIGGERED BOTH CIRCUITS.
TUCKER: DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT THE ODDS ARE
OF THAT HAPPENING?
CAN YOU SHUT THEM DOWN?
TUCKER: NOT FROM HERE.
SOMEONE'S GONNA HAVE
TO GO TO ENGINEERING.
PHLOX: REMEMBER, THE SUIT WILL
PROTECT YOU FOR ONLY 22 MINUTES.
IT'D BE BEST NOT TO TAKE
THE SCENIC ROUTE.
[ DOOR LATCH CLANGS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS DESCENDING ]
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
[ DOOR OPENING ]
TAKRETI: WE'VE SEARCHED
EVERY DECK.
THERE'S NO SIGN
OF THE FUGITIVES.
WHAT ABOUT THE CREW?
IT APPEARS THEY
HAVE DESERTED THE SHIP.
THESE HUMANS...
THEY'VE TRAVELED
OVER A HUNDRED LIGHT YEARS
FROM THEIR HOMEWORLD.
ARCHER'S VOICE: CAPTAIN'S
STARLOG, FEBRUARY 9, 2152.
THE VULCANS HAVE ALLOWED
THE MAZARITES TO LEAVE.
AMBASSADOR V'LAR SAYS
THERE'S--
ARCHER AND HIS CREW
MUST'VE TAKEN REFUGE
IN A NEARBY SYSTEM.
THEY MAY INTEND TO RETURN.
WHAT'S THE STATUS
OF THE WARP ENGINES?
I'M HAVING DIFFICULTY
WITH THE DILITHIUM MATRIX.
MAKE IT A PRIORITY.
ARCHER'S VOICE: ...2152.
WE'VE RESPONDED
TO A DISTRESS CALL
FROM A VESSEL IN THE...
PHLOX: THEY'RE IMMUNE
TO RADIOLYTIC ISOTOPES.
THE STORM WAS NEVER
ANY THREAT TO THEM.
TUCKER: FUNNY.
YOU DIDN'T MENTION THAT.
TAGRIM: WE WERE IN DANGER.
OUR SHIP IS
LESS DURABLE THAN YOURS.
WE WOULD'VE BEEN DESTROYED
BY THE STORM!
WHO ARE THEY?
WHAT ARE THEY DOING HERE?
CAPTAIN, I ASSURE YOU
WE DON'T KNOW THESE MEN.
THEY JUST HAPPENED
TO FIND ENTERPRISE
IN THE MIDDLE OF A CLASS-5
NEUTRONIC STORM?
WHERE THREE MEMBERS
OF THEIR OWN SPECIES
JUST HAPPENED TO
BE TAKING REFUGE?
T'POL: WE'RE MORE THAN 20
LIGHT YEARS FROM YOUR HOMEWORLD.
IT'S AN UNLIKELY COINCIDENCE.
ARCHER: I GET THE FEELING
THEY MUST BE LOOKING FOR YOU.
ANSWER ME!
GURI: I TOLD YOU WE SHOULDN'T
HAVE COME HERE.
GURI!
GURI: THEY'RE OFFICERS
OF THE TAKRET MILITIA.
THEY'VE BEEN
PURSUING US FOR WEEKS.
WE THOUGHT WE COULD EVADE THEM
BY HIDING ABOARD YOUR SHIP.
TAKRETI: THEY MUST'VE
DETECTED OUR VESSEL
IN YOUR LAUNCH BAY.
WHAT DO THEY WANT WITH YOU?
GURI: WE USED TO BE MEMBERS OF
THE MILITIA IN THE LOWER RANKS,
BUT, AFTER A YEAR,
WE REALIZED
THAT THE COMMANDING
OFFICERS WERE CORRUPT.
THEY SEIZE ALIEN VESSELS
WITHOUT PROVOCATION.
THEY MURDER THE CREWS,
TAKE ANYTHING OF VALUE.
TAKRETI: THEY'RE LITTLE MORE
THAN CRIMINALS.
TAGRIM: WE TRIED TO RESIGN
OUR COMMISSIONS,
BUT THEY WOULDN'T ALLOW IT.
-YOU'RE DESERTERS.
-WE HAD NO CHOICE.
TAGRIM: WE WOULD'VE TOLD
YOU THE TRUTH,
BUT WE WEREN'T SURE
THAT YOU WOULD HELP US.
GURI: IF THEY FIND US,
WE'LL BE EXECUTED.
TAGRIM: CAPTAIN, I APOLOGIZE
FOR THE DIFFICULT POSITION
THAT WE'VE PUT YOU IN,
BUT I KNOW THESE MEN.
EVEN IF THEY FOUND US,
I DOUBT THEY'D SIMPLY LEAVE.
THEY'VE CAPTURED VESSELS
FAR LESS IMPRESSIVE THAN YOURS.
REED: THEY'RE TRYING
TO RE-INITIALIZE
THE WARP REACTOR, SIR.
SEEMS TO ME THEY'VE
ALREADY DECIDED
TO HELP THEMSELVES
TO ENTERPRISE.
T'POL: THEY OBVIOUSLY DON'T
REALIZE WE'RE IN THE CATWALK.
IF THEY LEARN WE'RE HERE,
IT WOULD UNDOUBTEDLY
ENDANGER THE CREW.
TUCKER: WHAT'RE YOU SUGGESTING?
WE JUST SIT ON OUR HANDS
UNTIL THEY FIRE UP THE ENGINES?
YOU'RE ASSUMING THESE THREE
ARE TELLING THE TRUTH.
THEY'VE ALREADY LIED TO US.
TAGRIM: WE'RE NOT LYING.
THESE MEN ARE DANGEROUS.
Takreti: Paltani to Captain.
YES.
Paltani: The dilithium matrix
is active.
WE'RE READY TO INITIALIZE
THE WARP REACTOR.
Captain: Stand by.
DO WE HAVE HELM CONTROL?
TAKRETI: THE NAVIGATION RELAY
IS STILL NOT RESPONDING.
I THINK THEY'VE BEEN REROUTED.
HOW MUCH LONGER?
TAKRETI: I'M NOT CERTAIN.
CAPTAIN: BRING THE WARP
ENGINES ON LINE
and report to the bridge.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
T'POL: WE MAY OUTNUMBER THEM,
BUT WE ONLY HAVE
THREE E.V. SUITS.
REED: I COULD TAKE THE SECURITY
TEAM AND BRING BACK MORE.
TUCKER: I DOUBT YOU'D GET
VERY FAR.
THE LAUNCH BAY'S
CRAWLING WITH THEM.
ARCHER: EVEN IF WE COULD
GET THE SUITS,
WE ONLY HAVE 22 MINUTES
IN THE RADIATION.
HARD TO BELIEVE WE COULD
RETAKE THE SHIP IN THAT AM--
ARCHER: HOW LONG DO WE HAVE?
TUCKER: IT'LL TAKE A WHILE
FOR THE WARP COILS TO CHARGE.
ARCHER: HOW LONG?
TUCKER: 20 MINUTES TOPS.
TUCKER: REMEMBER,
JUNCTION 42-ALPHA.
T'POL: UNDERSTOOD.
TUCKER: THIRD PANEL, STARBOARD
SIDE, AND BE CAREFUL.
THERE'S A LOT OF CURRENT RUNNING
THROUGH THOSE CIRCUITS.
I REALLY OUGHT TO BE
THE ONE DOING THIS, CAPTAIN.
THE DOC SAID I WAS ONLY
OUT THERE FOR 13 MINUTES.
ARCHER: FORGET IT, TRIP.
YOU'VE ALREADY BEEN EXPOSED.
HOSHI: I'VE ISOLATED
YOUR COM FREQUENCIES.
THEY WON'T HEAR A THING.
TELL TRAVIS TO
WAIT FOR MY SIGNAL.
-ANY PROGRESS?
-NOT YET.
WE COULD LOSE OUR
SHIP BY STAYING HERE.
WE SHOULD TAKE WHAT
WE CAN AND LEAVE.
CAPTAIN: KEEP WORKING!
I WANT HELM CONTROL.
ARCHER: I'LL SEE YOU
BACK AT THE CATWALK.
DON'T BE LATE.
REED: AYE, CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: T'POL?
T'Pol: We're in position.
ALL RIGHT. FIRST, YOU'RE
GOING TO HAVE TO DISRUPT
THE ANTIMATTER STREAM.
Tucker: Do you see
the blue conduit to the left
of the power-transfer module?
GO AHEAD.
START BY LOCKING DOWN
THE FLOW REGULATORS.
STAND BY.
[ BEEPING ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
CAPTAIN: ANOTHER SHIP?
NO.
IT'S COMING
FROM WITHIN THIS VESSEL.
ANSWER IT.
YOU'RE IN MY CHAIR.
CAPTAIN: CAPTAIN ARCHER.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU WERE STILL ABOARD.
WHERE'S THE REST OF YOUR CREW?
THEY'RE DEAD,
KILLED BY THE STORM.
I'M SORRY.
THANKS FOR YOUR CONDOLENCES.
NOW, WHY DON'T YOU...
GET THE HELL OFF MY SHIP?
CAPTAIN: I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T DO THAT.
WE DETECTED A VESSEL
IN YOUR LAUNCH BAY
THAT BELONGS TO
THREE FUGITIVES.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING YOU...
[ GASPING ]
I KNOW YOU'RE TRYING
TO TAKE ENTERPRISE.
I'M NOT GOING TO LET YOU.
YOU'RE IN NO POSITION
TO DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
I AM IN COMMAND OF THIS BRIDGE.
YOUR VESSEL HAS BEEN IMPOUNDED
UNDER THE AUTHORITY
OF THE TAKRET MILITIA.
WHEN WE RETURN,
YOU'LL BE CHARGED
WITH CRIMINAL CONSPIRACY.
I DON'T RECOGNIZE
YOUR AUTHORITY!
I ANSWER TO STARFLEET COMMAND,
AND I'M UNDER ORDERS
TO USE ANY MEANS NECESSARY
TO KEEP MY SHIP
FROM FALLING INTO ENEMY HANDS.
I HAVE SOLDIERS
SEARCHING EVERY DECK.
IT'S ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THEY FIND YOU.
YOU'RE LEAVING ME...
...NO CHOICE.
I'LL DESTROY ENTERPRISE.
CAPTAIN: EARTH'S FIRST
WARP-5 STARSHIP?
YOUR FATHER'S ENGINE?
I'VE BEEN READING
ABOUT YOU, CAPTAIN.
I DOUBT VERY MUCH IF YOU'LL DO
ANYTHING TO DAMAGE THIS VESSEL.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
CAPTAIN: CAN YOU TRACE
HIS SIGNAL?
HE'S SOMEWHERE
ON THE FIFTH DECK.
YOU HAVE MEN THERE.
ALERT THEM.
GO AHEAD.
Archer: It's time
to change course, Travis.
Head straight
for that plasma eddy.
IT'LL TAKE A MINUTE, SIR.
Archer: Try to keep us
in one piece.
I'm on my way back.
Archer out.
WE'VE ALTERED COURSE.
CAPTAIN: WHERE'S HE TAKING US?
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM
SHUTTING DOWN THE REACTOR?
WE'RE HAVING TROUBLE
WITH THE DILITHIUM SEQUENCERS.
IT'S TAKING LONGER
THAN WE EXPECTED.
Tucker: I don't mean
to rush you,
BUT IT'S GETTING
PRETTY WARM IN HERE.
HE'S STEERING US
TOWARD A PLASMA EDDY.
CAPTAIN: HOW LONG?
LESS THAN EIGHT MINUTES.
GET ME HELM CONTROL!
IT'LL TAKE ME
MUCH LONGER THAN THAT.
WE SHOULD EVACUATE!
-NO!
-YOU HEARD WHAT HE SAID!
HE'S WILLING
TO DESTROY HIS OWN SHIP!
THE TEMPERATURE JUST WENT UP
ANOTHER SIX DEGREES.
SUBCOMMANDER, HOW'S IT COMING?
T'Pol: We're disabling
the final sequencer.
THE WARP REACTOR HAS SHUT DOWN.
TAKRETI: SPATIAL DISTURBANCE.
WE'RE FOUR MINUTES
FROM THE EDDY.
PALANTI: UNLESS YOU'VE FOUND
A WAY TO TURN THIS SHIP AROUND,
I STRONGLY SUGGEST
WE ABORT THE MISSION!
TAKRETI: THREE MINUTES!
CAPTAIN: SOLDIERS, REPORT TO
THE DOCKING HATCH IMMEDIATELY!
I REPEAT--
REPORT TO THE DOCKING HATCH!
T'POL: REPORT.
MAYWEATHER: WE'RE TOO CLOSE
TO THE EDDY.
-WE'VE GOT TO VEER OFF.
-MAINTAIN YOUR COURSE.
ANOTHER ONE LIKE THAT
WILL SPLIT US IN TWO.
THEY COULD STILL BE ON BOARD.
WE'VE GOT NO CHOICE.
MAINTAIN YOUR COURSE.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
T'POL: GO AHEAD.
Archer: Travis, I hope you're
not still heading for that eddy.
Our friends are gone.
ENSIGN.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE SEEM TO HAVE PASSED THROUGH
THE WORST PART OF THE STORM,
BUT IT'LL STILL BE A WHILE
BEFORE WE CAN LEAVE
THE CATWALK.
THE CREW'S IN
RELATIVELY GOOD SPIRITS,
CONSIDERING THEY HAVEN'T HAD
A CHANGE OF UNIFORM
IN EIGHT DAYS.
TUCKER: DID THAT GUY SHOOT
ONE OF HIS OWN MEN?
REED: IT'S HARD TO TELL THEM
APART IN THOSE RIDICULOUS HATS.
T'POL: THE DEAD MAN WAS SECRETLY
WORKING FOR SHERIFF BOGGS.
TUCKER: HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
T'POL: ISN'T IT OBVIOUS?
Archer: All hands,
this is the Captain.
THANKS TO SOME FINE PILOTING
BY TRAVIS MAYWEATHER,
WE'RE GOING TO BE MOVING OUT
OF THE STORM
A LITTLE EARLIER THAN EXPECTED.
WE SHOULD BE CLEAR
IN A FEW MINUTES.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
TUCKER: GLAD YOU COULD JOIN US,
SUBCOMMANDER.
WE HAVE MOVIE NIGHT
EVERY TUESDAY...
IF YOU'RE INTERESTED.
TAGRIM: I APOLOGIZE FOR
THE TROUBLE WE'VE CAUSED.
WHERE YOU HEADED NEXT?
TAGRIM: THE GYRANNAN SYSTEM.
WE SHOULD BE SAFE THERE.
GOOD LUCK.
THAT'S EVERYONE.