PHLOX: YOUR NEUROLYTIC ENZYMES
ARE CONSIDERABLY HIGHER
THAN LAST MONTH.
T'POL: THE TREATMENT'S
NO LONGER EFFECTIVE?
PHLOX: I TOLD YOU IT WAS
JUST A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE WE'D NEED
SUPPLEMENTAL MEDICATIONS.
THIS CONFERENCE
IS A PERFECT OPPORTUNITY.
SOME OF YOUR FINEST PHYSICIANS
WILL BE THERE.
IT'S ESSENTIAL
THAT I SPEAK WITH THEM.
T'POL: IT'S TOO GREAT A RISK.
I'D BE TAKEN OFF "ENTERPRISE."
PHLOX:
I THINK I CAN QUESTION THEM
WITHOUT REVEALING
THAT YOU'RE INFECTED.
T'POL: IT'S TOO GREAT A RISK.
PHLOX:
I'M AFRAID WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
WITHOUT FURTHER TREATMENT,
YOU COULD VERY POSSIBLY DIE.
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA
BEND OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER:
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE ENTERED ORBIT
OF DEKENDI III,
WHERE THE INTERSPECIES
MEDICAL EXCHANGE
IS HOSTING A CONFERENCE.
WE'LL BE PICKING UP
A NEUTRON MICROSCOPE,
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WE'LL GET A CHANCE
TO MEET ONE OF PHLOX'S WIVES.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN, DOC?
PHLOX: OH, I HAVEN'T SEEN
FEEZAL FOR NEARLY, UH, 4 YEARS.
TUCKER: WHAT'S THE POINT
OF HAVING THREE WIVES
IF YOU NEVER GET TO SEE THEM?
PHLOX: DENOBULANS ARE
RENOWNED FOR THEIR PATIENCE.
WELCOME, MY BELOVED!
FEEZAL: MY BELOVED.
[BOTH SNIFFING]
PHLOX:
CAPTAIN ARCHER, I'D LIKE YOU
TO MEET MY SECOND WIFE, FEEZAL.
ARCHER: IT'S A PLEASURE
TO HAVE YOU ABOARD.
FEEZAL: THANK YOU.
PHLOX: AND THIS IS OUR CHIEF
ENGINEER, COMMANDER TUCKER.
TUCKER: MA'AM.
FEEZAL: I LOOK FORWARD
TO HELPING YOU
INSTALL THE MICROSCOPE.
ARCHER:
WE CAN HOLD THAT OFF TILL LATER.
I'M SURE THE TWO OF YOU
ARE EAGER
TO SPEND SOME TIME TOGETHER.
PHLOX: NONSENSE, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE BEEN APART FOR FOUR YEARS.
ANOTHER HOUR, ANOTHER DAY.
AS I SAID, WE ARE VERY PATIENT.
ARCHER: WELL, IN THAT CASE,
WHY DON'T WE HAVE SOME LUNCH
WHILE THE MICROSCOPE'S
BEING UNLOADED?
FEEZAL: I'D BE HONORED.
FEEZAL: WON'T YOU BE
JOINING US, COMMANDER?
TUCKER: OH, I'D LOVE TO,
BUT I THINK I SHOULD MAKE SURE
YOUR EQUIPMENT GETS UP
TO SICK BAY IN ONE PIECE.
FEEZAL:
THEN I'LL SEE YOU AFTER LUNCH?
TUCKER: YOU BET.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
ANNOUNCER:
THE CORIDAN GENOME CONFERENCE
HAS BEEN RESCHEDULED
FOR 1400 HOURS IN AUDITORIUM 6.
YURIS: IT SEEMS ODD, DOESN'T IT,
THAT A DENOBULAN PHYSICIAN
WOULD BE INTERESTED
IN A VULCAN DISEASE?
PHLOX: ONE OF MY COLLEAGUES
ON DENOBULA
HAS BEEN STUDYING
PA'NAR SYNDROME FOR SOME TIME.
ITS PATHOLOGY IS QUITE SIMILAR
TO THYMIC SCLEROSIS.
STROM: THYMIC SCLEROSIS?
PHLOX: IT'S, UH,
A NONFATAL ILLNESS
WHICH WE'VE HAD
VERY LITTLE SUCCESS TREATING.
I PROMISED HIM,
MY COLLEAGUE BACK HOME,
THAT I'D INQUIRE ABOUT
ANY RECENT ADVANCES
IN ITS TREATMENT.
ORATT: WE'RE HESITANT TO
DISCUSS PA'NAR SYNDROME, DOCTOR.
THIS ILLNESS IS UNIQUE
TO A SUBCULTURE,
A SMALL PERCENTAGE
OF OUR POPULATION.
THEIR BEHAVIOR IS NEITHER
TOLERATED NOR SANCTIONED.
PHLOX:
MY FRIEND IS WELL AWARE OF THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY, THYMIC SCLEROSIS
IS FOUND IN ALL STRATA
OF DENOBULAN SOCIETY.
DEVELOPING A CURE
IS OF PARAMOUNT IMPORTANCE.
YURIS: DO YOU HAVE
ANY LITERATURE ON THIS DISEASE?
PHLOX: AS I TOLD YOU,
I'M CURRENTLY SERVING
ON A STARFLEET VESSEL.
HUMANS ARE NOT
SUSCEPTIBLE TO IT.
I COULD, UH, CONTACT
MY COLLEAGUE,
BUT IT WOULD TAKE
AT LEAST FIVE DAYS
BEFORE WE'D RECEIVE A RESPONSE.
STROM: I'M AFRAID WE'LL
HAVE RETURNED TO VULCAN BY THEN.
PHLOX: ANYTHING YOU COULD
PROVIDE ME WITH
WOULD BE INSTRUMENTAL
IN HELPING THE DENOBULAN PEOPLE.
ORATT: WE'LL HAVE
TO DISCUSS YOUR REQUEST, DOCTOR.
WHEN WE'VE REACHED A DECISION,
WE'LL CONTACT YOU
ABOARD YOUR SHIP.
PHLOX: THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
TUCKER: IF THE REFLECTOMETER
IS SUPPOSED TO AMPLIFY
THE NEUTRON STREAM,
SHOULDN'T IT BE INSTALLED
BEFORE THE EMITTERS?
FEEZAL: IT'S COLLIMATING
THE NEUTRONS,
NOT AMPLIFYING THEM.
IF YOU READ THE INSTRUCTIONS,
YOU'LL FIND IT'S ALL VERY CLEAR.
TUCKER: OH, I'VE TRIED TO READ
THE INSTRUCTIONS,
AND THEY ARE ANYTHING BUT CLEAR.
I DON'T WANT TO BRAG,
BUT I CAN TAKE APART
AND PUT BACK TOGETHER
JUST ABOUT ANY PIECE
OF EQUIPMENT I'VE EVER MET.
THAT'S ONE OF THE REASONS
CAPTAIN ARCHER PICKED ME
FOR THIS MISSION,
BECAUSE I AM REALLY GOOD
AT FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS.
BUT THESE ARE IN...
FEEZAL: DENOBULAN.
I UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
SO LET'S GO THROUGH IT SLOWLY.
DO YOU SEE THE THREADS
ON THE APERTURE RING?
TUCKER: HERE.
FEEZAL: EXACTLY.
TAKE THE SMALLER
CONDENSER LENS AND SCREW IT ON.
NOW REMODULATE
THE EMITTER FREQUENCY.
THAT'LL INITIATE
THE NEUTRON STREAM.
TUCKER: UH, WHICH ONE?
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO HELP ME
WITH THIS ONE.
FEEZAL: IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
INSERT THE THICK END
INTO THIS OPENING.
IT'LL AUTOMATICALLY PROGRAM
THE FREQUENCY.
YOU CAN PULL IT OUT NOW.
THE STREAM SHOULD BE INITIATED.
TUCKER: UH, I THINK I'M GETTING
THE HANG OF IT. UH...
MAYBE IF YOU EXPLAIN
THE NEXT FEW STEPS,
I COULD TRY AND GET THROUGH
SOME OF THIS ON MY OWN.
FEEZAL: BY ALL MEANS.
YOU'RE A VERY CONFIDENT
YOUNG MAN, AREN'T YOU?
TUCKER: I TRY TO BE.
FEEZAL:
YOU'RE GOING TO NEED TO COME
A LITTLE CLOSER TO SEE THIS.
ARCHER: HAVE YOU SPOKEN
TO PHLOX SINCE HE GOT BACK?
T'POL: I WASN'T AWARE
HE WAS GONE.
ARCHER: YOU MUST'VE NOT
SEEN HIM YESTERDAY MORNING.
HE WAS CHAMPING AT THE BIT TO
GET DOWN TO THAT CONFERENCE.
BROUGHT BACK A WISH LIST
OF MEDICAL INSTRUMENTS.
T'POL: IT IS THE FIRST I.M.E.
CONFERENCE HE'S ATTENDED
IN OVER A YEAR.
ARCHER: HE SAID THERE WAS
A VULCAN CONTINGENT.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO GO DOWN
FOR A VISIT.
YOU MAY KNOW ONE OF THEM.
T'POL: THERE ARE OVER
1 MILLION PHYSICIANS ON VULCAN.
ARCHER: I WOULD THINK YOU'D
ENJOY SPENDING TIME
WITH MEMBERS
OF YOUR OWN SPECIES.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
ARCHER.
HOSHI: A Vulcan transport
has requested
permission to dock, sir.
They've already left
the surface.
ARCHER: SPEAK OF THE DEVIL.
LOOKS LIKE YOU WON'T
HAVE TO GO ANYWHERE.
I'LL MEET THEM
AT DOCKING PORT 2.
HOSHI: They've asked
that the doctor join you
and Sub-commander T'Pol.
ARCHER: LET HIM KNOW, OK?
HOSHI: Right away, sir.
ARCHER: YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT THIS IS ABOUT?
T'POL: I HAVEN'T SPOKEN
TO ANYONE ON THE SURFACE.
ARCHER: YOU CAN BET
THEY'RE NOT COMING UP
FOR COFFEE AND DOUGHNUTS.
CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING?
THANKS TO SUB-COMMANDER T'POL,
OUR CHEF HAS LEARNED
TO MAKE SOME PRETTY DECENT
PLOMEEK SOUP.
ORATT: WE APPRECIATE
YOUR HOSPITALITY, CAPTAIN,
BUT WE'VE COME TO SPEAK
TO YOUR DOCTOR...
WITH YOUR PERMISSION.
ARCHER: ABSOLUTELY.
IF YOU NEED ANYTHING,
JUST LET ME KNOW.
ORATT: WE WOULD APPRECIATE IT
IF T'POL WOULD REMAIN.
ARCHER: SUB-COMMANDER.
ORATT:
WE'VE DISCUSSED YOUR REQUEST.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE ARE STILL HESITANT
TO SHARE DATA
REGARDING PA'NAR SYNDROME.
PHLOX: SUB-COMMANDER T'POL
IS NOT AWARE OF MY REQUEST.
I'M, UH, CURIOUS WHY YOU
ASKED HER TO STAY.
YURIS:
YOU'RE REQUESTING INFORMATION
ABOUT A VULCAN DISEASE,
AND YOU DIDN'T DISCUSS IT WITH
YOUR VULCAN SCIENCE OFFICER?
PHLOX: THAT'S CORRECT.
AS FAR AS I KNOW, HER EXPERTISE
DOES NOT INCLUDE MEDICINE.
ORATT: ARE YOU FAMILIAR WITH
PA'NAR SYNDROME, SUB-COMMANDER?
T'POL: OF COURSE.
ORATT:
WOULD YOU MIND DESCRIBING IT?
T'POL: YOU'RE PHYSICIANS.
WHY WOULD YOU NEED ME
TO DEFINE AN ILLNESS?
ORATT: PLEASE. INDULGE US.
T'POL:
IT'S AN INCURABLE DEGRADATION
OF THE SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS.
IT ALSO AFFECTS THE ENDOCRINE
AND IMMUNE SYSTEMS.
STROM:
AN IMPRESSIVE DEFINITION.
COULD YOU TELL US HOW
THE DISEASE IS TRANSMITTED?
T'POL:
THROUGH A TELEPATHIC PRACTICE.
ORATT:
AND WHAT PRACTICE WOULD THAT BE?
T'POL: MIND-MELDS.
THEY CAUSE A DISRUPTION
OF NEUROELECTRIC IMPULSES
IN THE MID-BRAIN,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO THE EARLY
STAGES OF THE SYNDROME.
STROM: DO YOU CONDONE
THESE ACTS, SUB-COMMANDER,
THESE MIND-MELDS?
T'POL: I'D APPRECIATE
IT IF YOU'D TELL ME
WHY YOU ASKED ME HERE.
PHLOX: AS WOULD I.
YOUR QUESTIONS TO T'POL
SEEM INAPPROPRIATE.
ORATT:
DR. PHLOX HAS ASKED FOR DATA
REGARDING THE TREATMENT
OF PA'NAR SYNDROME.
DID YOU HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH THAT REQUEST?
PHLOX: I BELIEVE I WAS
VERY CLEAR ABOUT THAT.
STROM:
YES, YOUR COLLEAGUE ON DENOBULA.
FORGIVE US, DOCTOR,
BUT SINCE THERE'S A VULCAN
SERVING ON YOUR SHIP,
A FACT THAT YOU NEGLECTED
TO MENTION TO US,
WE HAD TO CONSIDER
OTHER POSSIBLE MOTIVES
FOR YOUR INQUIRY.
PHLOX:
WHAT MOTIVE ARE YOU SUGGESTING?
STROM: ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH ANY OF THESE NAMES?
T'POL: THEY'RE VULCAN.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH ANY OF THEM.
STROM: THEY'RE MELDERS,
VULCANS WITH THE ABILITY
TO TRANSFER THOUGHTS
AND MEMORIES TO EACH OTHER.
DO YOU KNOW ANY MELDERS,
SUB-COMMANDER?
T'POL: NOT WELL,
BUT I'VE MET A NUMBER OF THEM.
STROM: THEN I'LL ASK YOU AGAIN.
DO YOU CONDONE THEIR BEHAVIOR?
T'POL: I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOUR QUESTIONS HAVE TO DO
WITH THE DOCTOR'S REQUEST.
ORATT: WE FIND
THEIR BEHAVIOR UNACCEPTABLE.
AND SINCE PA'NAR SYNDROME
IS TRANSMITTED BY THESE PEOPLE,
ITS CURE IS NOT A PRIORITY.
PHLOX: ARE YOU SAYING
THERE IS NO ADDITIONAL RESEARCH?
ORATT: NONE THAT WE'D CARE
TO DISSEMINATE.
I'M SORRY.
T'POL:
YOU TRAVELED UP FROM THE SURFACE
TO TELL DR. PHLOX
YOU WOULDN'T HELP HIM?
ORATT: IF YOU'LL PLEASE
SHOW US TO THE AIRLOCK.
YURIS: IS IT DEFINITIVE?
STROM: UNMISTAKABLY.
SHE'S SUFFERING
FROM THE SYNDROME.
FEEZAL: NOW WATCH.
A SIMPLE STRAND OF PROTEIN
MOLECULES CAN BE ENLARGED...
AND ENHANCED...
TO WHERE WE CAN CLEARLY SEE
A SINGLE NUCLEOTIDE.
TUCKER: AMAZING!
LOOK AT THAT. ARE THOSE--
FEEZAL: CARBON ATOMS.
NOW YOU TRY IT.
TUCKER: FIRST I REINITIALIZE
THE NEUTRON STREAM.
FEEZAL: PRECISELY.
VERY GOOD.
NOW ALIGN THE QUANTUM FILTERS.
TUCKER: THIS IS A BITCH.
FEEZAL: EXCUSE ME?
TUCKER: OH, NOT YOU.
UH...THE--THE MICROSCOPE.
PHLOX:
HAS VESENA FORGIVEN GROZNIK YET?
FEEZAL: ABSOLUTELY NOT.
GROZNIK HAS ONLY
APOLOGIZED TWICE.
I DOUBT HE'LL BE FORGIVEN
FOR ANOTHER TWO YEARS.
PHLOX: WELL, AT LEAST HE HAS
HIS OTHER WIVES.
FEEZAL: NOT WIVES. WIFE.
KESSIL MOVED TO TEERZA PRIME
TO BE WITH HER THIRD HUSBAND.
TUCKER: DID I DO THIS RIGHT?
WHY IS THERE NO IMAGE?
FEEZAL: YOU FORGOT TO ENTER
THE FREQUENCY PARAMETERS.
PHLOX:
WHICH ONE WAS HER THIRD HUSBAND?
OH, WAS THAT KLABAN?
BOGGA.
KLABAN WAS FORLISA'S HUSBAND.
HER FIRST, I THINK.
TUCKER: THERE YOU GO.
WHY ISN'T IT SHARP?
FEEZAL: YOU FORGOT TO STABILIZE
THE APERTURE.
THAT'S JUST A REFLECTION
FROM THE IMAGING FILAMENT.
[TUCKER CHUCKLES]
FEEZAL: THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL REINITIALIZE THE NEUTRON
STREAM AND START AGAIN.
PHLOX: FORLISA. HA HA!
FORLISA. OH, MY, MY.
I, UH, THOUGHT ABOUT ASKING
FORLISA
TO BE MY SECOND WIFE.
TURNED OUT SHE ALREADY HAD
THREE HUSBANDS.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
Archer to Dr. Phlox.
YES, CAPTAIN.
Could you report
to my ready room?
CERTAINLY.
I'LL BE BACK AS SOON AS I CAN,
MY BELOVED.
COMMANDER.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
PHLOX: YES, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER:
I WANTED TO SEE BOTH OF YOU.
IT'S BEEN A WHILE
SINCE I WAS EMBARRASSED
BY A VULCAN DIGNITARY.
PHLOX: SIR?
ARCHER:
I JUST SPOKE TO DR. ORATT.
IT SEEMS YOU REQUESTED
SOME MEDICAL DATA
REGARDING A VULCAN ILLNESS...
FOR A COLLEAGUE ON DENOBULA.
PHLOX: YES, SIR.
ARCHER: AND BOTH OF YOU SAID
THAT T'POL HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH THAT REQUEST.
ARE YOU BOTH GOING TO
LIE TO ME LIKE YOU LIED TO THEM?
PHLOX: I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF LYING TO YOU, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: AND WHEN WERE YOU
GOING TO TELL ME
THAT YOU'VE CONTRACTED
A SERIOUS ILLNESS?
T'POL: SIR?
ARCHER: THEY HANDED YOU
SOMETHING--A PADD, I THINK.
DOES THAT RING A BELL?
YOU LEFT A FINGERPRINT.
IT WAS ENOUGH
FOR THEM TO RUN TESTS.
WHY DID YOU LIE TO THEM?
T'POL:
IT'S NONE OF THEIR CONCERN.
ARCHER: IT SURE AS HELL IS
IF THEY CAN HELP YOU.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
KNOWN ABOUT THIS?
PHLOX: NEARLY A YEAR.
ARCHER: AND YOU NEVER THOUGHT
THAT MAYBE YOU SHOULD COME TO ME
AND LET ME KNOW
THAT ONE OF MY OFFICERS
HAS A POTENTIALLY FATAL DISEASE?
PHLOX: I BELIEVE YOUR CULTURE
EMBRACES THE CONCEPT
OF DOCTOR-PATIENT
CONFIDENTIALITY.
T'POL:
THE DISEASE IS NOT CONTAGIOUS.
IF WE HAD TOLD YOU, THERE'S
NOTHING YOU COULD HAVE DONE.
ARCHER: YOU STILL
HAVEN'T EXPLAINED TO ME
WHY YOU LIED TO THE VULCANS.
AND WHY WOULD YOU THINK THEY
WOULD BE MORE APT TO HELP
YOU IF YOU SAID IT WAS
FOR A DENOBULAN COLLEAGUE?
PHLOX:
PA'NAR SYNDROME IS AN ILLNESS
THAT CARRIES A STIGMA ON VULCAN.
TUCKER: IF THE HIGH COMMAND WAS
TO LEARN THAT I WAS INFECTED,
I WOULD MOST LIKELY
LOSE MY COMMISSION.
ARCHER: FOR HAVING A DISEASE?
T'POL: IT'S NOT
ABOUT THE DISEASE.
IT'S ABOUT THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE CAPABLE OF TRANSMITTING IT.
ARCHER: GO ON.
T'POL: THERE ARE CERTAIN
VULCANS, A SMALL MINORITY,
WHO ARE BORN WITH THE ABILITY
TO PERFORM A VERY INTIMATE
FORM OF TELEPATHY.
ARCHER: INTIMATE?
T'POL: A MELDING OF MINDS.
ARCHER:
THAT SHIP OF VULCANS WHO WERE
EXPERIMENTING WITH EMOTIONS.
T'POL: THEY ARE PART
OF THE TELEPATHIC MINORITY.
ONE OF THE REASONS WHY THEY LEFT
VULCAN WAS TO ESCAPE PREJUDICE.
THEIR BEHAVIOR
IS CONSIDERED UNNATURAL.
THEY'RE SEEN AS A THREAT.
ARCHER: YOU BELONG
TO THAT MINORITY.
T'POL: NO.
ARCHER: THEN--
PHLOX: ONLY MEMBERS
OF THE MINORITY
CAN INITIATE A MIND-MELD,
BUT ANY VULCAN
CAN BE THE RECIPIENT.
ARCHER:
WHY WOULD YOU TAKE THAT RISK?
T'POL: IT WASN'T BY CHOICE.
ONE OF THE MEN ON THAT SHIP...
ARCHER: YOU WERE ATTACKED.
I REMEMBER.
I'M SURE THE HIGH COMMAND
WILL UNDERSTAND.
T'POL: I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF TELLING THEM.
ARCHER: WHY NOT?
T'POL: I HAVE MY REASONS.
ARCHER: HOW SERIOUS IS IT?
PHLOX: I'VE KEPT IT IN CHECK,
BUT THE SYMPTOMS
HAVE PROGRESSED.
THAT'S WHY I REQUESTED
THE MOST CURRENT RESEARCH.
ARCHER: WELL, YOUR REQUEST
WAS ACCOMPANIED BY A LIE.
AND WHATEVER YOUR REASONS
MIGHT HAVE BEEN,
YOU'RE NO LONGER WELCOME
AT THE CONFERENCE.
THE VULCANS HAVE SEEN TO THAT.
PHLOX: I UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: MY NUMBER-ONE
PRIORITY HERE
IS THE HEALTH
OF MY FIRST OFFICER.
IF THESE DOCTORS HAVE DATA
THAT CAN HELP HER...
I PLAN TO GET IT.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
STROM: I'M SORRY.
DID WE KEEP YOU WAITING?
ARCHER: ACTUALLY...YOU DID.
STROM: WHAT CAN WE DO
FOR YOU, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: SUB-COMMANDER T'POL
AND MY DOCTOR
HAVE EXPLAINED
THE SITUATION TO ME.
STROM: OH.
IT'S UNFORTUNATE
THAT T'POL IS ILL.
ARCHER: DR. PHLOX ASSURES ME
THAT HE WAS ONLY TRYING
TO PROTECT HER PRIVACY.
HE DOESN'T MAKE
A HABIT OF LYING.
STROM: I CERTAINLY HOPE NOT.
ARCHER:
I'M HAVING A LITTLE DIFFICULTY
UNDERSTANDING WHY YOU
WON'T SHARE YOUR RESEARCH,
ESPECIALLY NOW THAT YOU KNOW
IT COULD HELP T'POL'S CONDITION.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU'RE WITHHOLDING IT
TO PUNISH DR. PHLOX.
STROM: OUR DECISION
HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH THAT.
ARCHER: THEN WHAT DOES IT
HAVE TO DO WITH?
STROM: PA'NAR SYNDROME IS
A DISEASE THAT'S UNIQUE
TO AN UNDESIRABLE SEGMENT
OF OUR POPULATION.
THANKFULLY,
THERE ARE VERY FEW OF THEM.
ARCHER: AND BECAUSE YOU
FIND THEM UNDESIRABLE...
THEY'RE NOT ENTITLED
TO MEDICAL CARE?
STROM: WE DON'T CONDONE
THE INTIMATE ACTS
THAT THESE PEOPLE ENGAGE IN.
THEY DEFY EVERYTHING
OUR SOCIETY STANDS FOR.
ARCHER: INTIMATE ACTS?
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT MIND-MELDS.
STROM: WE TAKE GREAT PRIDE IN
OUR ABILITY TO CONTAIN EMOTIONS.
SHARING THEM IS OFFENSIVE.
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
WE HAVE A GREAT DEAL OF WORK TO
DO BEFORE THE CONFERENCE ENDS.
ARCHER:
IF YOU'RE NOT GOING TO HELP HER,
THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
IS SHOW A LITTLE DISCRETION.
THE HIGH COMMAND DOESN'T
NEED TO KNOW ABOUT THIS.
STROM:
IT'S NOT FOR US TO DECIDE
WHAT THE HIGH COMMAND
NEEDS TO KNOW.
ARCHER:
YOU HAVE HER GENETIC PROFILE.
YOU MUST REALIZE SHE'S NOT
A MEMBER OF THIS MINORITY.
STROM: NONETHELESS,
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
TO CONTRACT PA'NAR SYNDROME.
GOOD DAY.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
YES.
HOSHI: There's a message for you
coming from the surface.
TRANSFER IT HERE.
Right away.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
AH.
I WAS JUST ABOUT TO CALL YOU.
SIT DOWN.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T HAVE
MUCH LUCK DOWN THERE.
THEY SEEM PRETTY...
PIGHEADED WHEN IT COMES
TO PA'NAR SYNDROME.
AND I GOT THE DISTINCT FEELING
THEY'RE NOT GONNA KEEP THIS
TO THEMSELVES.
T'POL: I JUST RECEIVED A MESSAGE
FROM DR. YURIS.
ARCHER: WHICH ONE IS HE?
T'POL: THE YOUNGEST.
HE ASKED ME TO MEET HIM
IN A NORTHERN SECTION
OF THE CITY.
I BELIEVE HE WANTS TO HELP.
ARCHER: HELP?
THAT SEEMS LIKE THE LAST THING
THESE DOCTORS WANT TO DO.
T'POL: HE ASKED ME
TO COME ALONE.
YURIS: SUB-COMMANDER.
THIS MAY BE OF USE TO YOU.
T'POL: WHAT IS IT?
YURIS: THE RESEARCH
YOUR DOCTOR ASKED FOR.
T'POL: YOU'VE TAKEN A GREAT RISK
BY BRINGING THIS TO ME.
YURIS: ONE THAT I'M MORE
THAN WILLING TO TAKE.
T'POL: WHY?
YURIS: THERE'S
MORE INTOLERANCE TODAY
THAN THERE WAS
A THOUSAND YEARS AGO.
IT HAS TO STOP.
T'POL: WHY JEOPARDIZE
YOUR CAREER
TO HELP SOMEONE YOU DESPISE?
YURIS: IF I DESPISED YOU,
I'D BE DESPISING MYSELF.
I'M PART OF THE MINORITY.
T'POL: YOU KNOW I'M NOT
A MEMBER OF THE MINORITY.
YURIS: AS FAR AS
MY COLLEAGUES ARE CONCERNED,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL BE.
ANYONE WHO CHOOSES
TO PERFORM A MIND-MELD
IS WORTHY OF CONTEMPT.
T'POL: WHAT IF I DIDN'T CHOOSE?
YURIS: YOU WERE COERCED.
YOU SHOULD TELL THEM.
THEY'LL BE FAR MORE SYMPATHETIC.
T'POL: ARE YOU INFECTED?
YURIS: NO.
ONLY A SMALL PERCENTAGE ARE.
IF THEY ASK MY OPINION, I WON'T
BE ABLE TO CONDONE WHAT YOU DID.
I HOPE YOU UNDERSTAND.
T'POL: YOU CAN'T JEOPARDIZE
YOUR POSITION.
YURIS: I HAVE TO RETURN.
TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED.
TELL THEM BEFORE THEY
CONTACT THE HIGH COMMAND.
T'POL: THANK YOU FOR THIS.
HOSHI:
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
TUCKER: WHY NOT?
HOSHI: WE'RE ORBITING
AN ALIEN WORLD,
AND MOST OF THE CREW
ARE FREE TO GO DOWN AND VISIT.
WHY WOULD ANYONE WANT TO STAY
ON BOARD AND WATCH A MOVIE?
TUCKER: ARE YOU KIDDING?
THEY'RE SHOWING "THE BLACK CAT."
BORIS KARLOFF AND BELA LUGOSI.
HOSHI: IT SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE
THE ONE PICKING THE MOVIES.
TUCKER: ME?
HOSHI: WHO ELSE WOULD CHOOSE
AN OBSCURE HORROR FILM?
WHY NOT SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE--
I DON'T KNOW--ROMANTIC?
I'M GOING DOWN TO THE SURFACE.
TUCKER: W-WHAT'S THE RUSH?
YOU--YOU HAVEN'T EVEN
FINISHED YOUR DINNER.
HOSHI: THERE'S A SHUTTLE
LEAVING AT 1800 HOURS.
TUCKER: YOU GOT PLENTY OF TIME.
TRY THE COBBLER.
CHEF OUTDID HIMSELF.
HOSHI: OK, BUT I HAVE TO LEAVE
IN A FEW MINUTES.
FEEZAL: MAY I JOIN YOU?
HOSHI: PLEASE. I'M HOSHI SATO.
I'VE BEEN MEANING
TO INTRODUCE MYSELF.
FEEZAL PHLOX.
YOU'RE THE LANGUAGE WIZARD.
MY HUSBAND SPEAKS
VERY FONDLY OF YOU.
TUCKER: I'M GETTING
A LITTLE PARANOID HERE.
YOU'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT ME, ARE YOU?
HOSHI: MATTER OF FACT, WE WERE.
FEEZAL: ENSIGN SATO
BARELY HAS AN ACCENT.
SHE WAS TELLING ME HOW
ATTRACTIVE SHE THINKS YOU ARE.
HOSHI: SHE'S PULLING
YOUR LEG, SIR.
I WAS ONLY TALKING
ABOUT GRAMMAR.
TUCKER: IT'S OK, HOSHI.
HOSHI: I'VE GOT TO GO.
IT WAS VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
FEEZAL: I WASN'T EXACTLY PULLING
YOUR LEG, WAS I?
TUCKER: NO, NOT EXACTLY.
LOOK, UH...
[CHUCKLES]
UH, I'M VERY FLATTERED,
BUT AREN'T YOU A MARRIED WOMAN?
FEEZAL: I'M A WOMAN.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS,
ISN'T IT?
TUCKER: UH...I'M AFRAID
I'VE GOT TO GO, TOO.
UM, CAPTAIN ASKED ME TO WRITE
A SYNOPSIS OF TONIGHT'S MOVIE.
FEEZAL: SAVE ME A SEAT.
TUCKER:
YOU PROBABLY WOULDN'T LIKE IT.
IT'S VERY SCARY,
AND, UH, YOU'VE GOT TO...
YOU'VE GOT TO BE HUMAN
TO APPRECIATE HORROR FILMS.
I'LL SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
SHE'S AT IT AGAIN!
REED: I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I FIND HER QUITE ATTRACTIVE.
TUCKER: COME ON, MALCOLM,
THIS IS SERIOUS!
WHAT IF PHLOX FINDS OUT?
REED: YOU HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING
TO MAKE HER THINK THAT YOU...
TUCKER: OF COURSE NOT!
MAYBE I SHOULD TELL THE DOC.
REED: TELL HIM WHAT?
THAT HIS WIFE
IS TRYING TO SEDUCE YOU?
NOT A GOOD IDEA.
TUCKER: BUT I'VE GOT TO SPEND
THE NEXT TWO DAYS WITH HER
WORKING ON THE MICROSCOPE.
I REALLY THINK
I SHOULD SPEAK TO PHLOX.
REED: IT MIGHT BE A LOT EASIER
TO AVOID HER ADVANCES
THAN GET PHLOX ANGRY.
I ONCE SAW HIM LOSE HIS TEMPER
WHEN ONE OF HIS CREATURES
BIT HIM.
HA HA! IT WASN'T A PRETTY SIGHT.
[TUCKER SIGHS]
PHLOX: THIS IS FAR FROM A CURE,
BUT IT, UH, SHOULD SLOW DOWN
THE PROGRESSION OF THE DISEASE.
IT'S SURPRISING.
I ASSUMED
YOUR SCIENCE DIRECTORATE
WOULD'VE MADE MORE PROGRESS
THAN THIS.
T'POL: AS WE'VE SEEN,
THEY'RE NOT VERY MOTIVATED
TO DEVELOP A CURE.
PHLOX: HMM, WITH THIS RESEARCH,
I SHOULD BE ABLE TO GET CLOSER
THAN THEY HAVE.
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER: HOW USEFUL IS IT?
PHLOX: VERY.
IT WILL ALLOW ME TO IMPROVE
MY COURSE OF TREATMENT
LONG BEFORE HER SYMPTOMS
GET WORSE.
ARCHER: HAVE YOU FIGURED OUT
WHY DR. YURIS GAVE IT TO YOU?
T'POL: NO, I HAVEN'T.
YOU SPOKE WITH THEM.
ARCHER: A FEW MINUTES AGO.
THEY'VE DECIDED TO RECALL YOU.
PHLOX: DO THEY HAVE
THE AUTHORITY TO DO THAT?
ARCHER: DR. ORATT DOES.
HE'S A RANKING MEMBER
OF THE COUNCIL OF PHYSICIANS.
THEY PLAN ON TAKING YOU
BACK TO VULCAN
WHEN THE CONFERENCE IS OVER.
T'POL: HAVE THEY NOTIFIED
THE HIGH COMMAND?
ARCHER: NOT TILL
YOU REACH VULCAN.
YOU'VE GOT TO TELL THEM, T'POL.
TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED.
THEY WON'T DO A THING TO YOU
ONCE THEY KNOW
IT WASN'T VOLUNTARY,
THAT HE DID IT
AGAINST YOUR WILL.
T'POL: I WON'T DO THAT.
ARCHER: WHY THE HELL NOT?!
T'POL: I HAVE PA'NAR SYNDROME.
DOESN'T MAKE A DIFFERENCE
HOW I CONTRACTED IT.
ARCHER:
IT MAKES A LOT OF DIFFERENCE!
YOU'RE NOT A MEMBER
OF THIS MINORITY.
HE FORCED HIMSELF ON YOU.
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF!
PHLOX: HE'S RIGHT, T'POL.
YOU SHOULD TELL THEM.
T'POL: HE'S NOT RIGHT.
IF I USE THAT AS A DEFENSE
AS A WAY TO KEEP FROM BEING
TAKEN OFF "ENTERPRISE,"
I'D BE CONDONING THEIR PREJUDICE
AND IN THE PROCESS INDICTING
EVERY MEMBER OF THE MINORITY.
I WON'T DO THAT.
ARCHER: WHERE'S ORATT?
VULCAN:
DR. ORATT ISN'T AVAILABLE.
VULCAN: PERHAPS I CAN HELP YOU.
ARCHER: PERHAPS YOU CAN'T.
VULCAN:
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO LEAVE.
ARCHER: I NEED TO TALK TO YOU!
VULCAN: I TOLD HIM
YOU WERE BUSY.
ORATT:
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO TAKE MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
ORATT: YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
I HAVE EVERY RIGHT.
ARCHER: YOU CAN'T DISMISS
SOMEONE
JUST BECAUSE YOU DON'T AGREE
WITH THE WAY THEY CONDUCT
THEIR PERSONAL LIVES!
ORATT: I AM NOT
DISMISSING T'POL.
I'M SIMPLY RETURNING HER
TO VULCAN.
THE HIGH COMMAND WILL DECIDE
WHETHER SHE IS FIT FOR DUTY.
ARCHER: FIT?!
YOU'RE SAYING A SINGLE MIND-MELD
IS ENOUGH TO DESTROY HER CAREER?
OR IS IT THAT SHE
CONTRACTED THE DISEASE?
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE
SO HESITANT TO FIND A CURE,
ISN'T IT?
WHY BOTHER TO HELP PEOPLE
YOU DON'T APPROVE OF?
ORATT:
I'M SORRY YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE COMPLEXITIES
OF OUR CULTURE, CAPTAIN.
PLEASE HAVE THE SUB-COMMANDER
READY TO DEPART IN 36 HOURS.
ARCHER: NOT SO FAST.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS, DOCTOR?
MY COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER GOT IT
FROM THE VULCAN DATABASE.
IT'S THE PROTOCOLS
OF THE COUNCIL OF PHYSICIANS.
IT SAYS THAT ANYONE ACCUSED
OF ETHICAL MISCONDUCT
IS ENTITLED TO A HEARING
"BEFORE THE RANKING
"MEDICAL OFFICER
IN THE PROVINCE OR TERRITORY
WHERE THE ACCUSATION
WAS FIRST MADE."
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
THAT WOULD BE YOU.
ORATT: THE ACCUSATION
AGAINST T'POL STANDS.
IT'S NOT OPEN
FOR DEBATE.
ARCHER: WHERE I COME FROM,
EVERYTHING'S OPEN FOR DEBATE.
AND IF I READ THESE PROTOCOLS
CORRECTLY,
SO IS THE ACCUSATION YOU MADE
AGAINST MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
ORATT: YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME.
ARCHER: IT'S MINE TO WASTE.
ORATT: VERY WELL.
BUT I WILL NOT DELAY
OUR DEPARTURE.
THE HEARING WILL TAKE PLACE
TOMORROW AFTERNOON.
ARCHER: TOMORROW AFTERNOON.
FINE.
TRAVIS: IT'S THE DEKENDI'S
FAVORITE SPORT.
PHLOX: JUST BECAUSE THEY
ASKED YOU TO PARTICIPATE
DOESN'T MEAN YOU HAD TO.
TRAVIS: THEY SAID
IT WAS AN HONOR.
IT LOOKED EASY ENOUGH.
PHLOX: YOU'RE LUCKY
THIS CREATURE
DIDN'T STRIKE A BIT LOWER.
IF I MAY ASK, WHAT IS
THE PURPOSE OF THIS, UH, SPORT?
TRAVIS: THEY'VE GOT
THESE FARGANS.
THEY'RE KIND OF LIKE
COWS WITH HUMPS,
AND THEY LOVE MELONS.
I THINK THEY'RE MELONS.
SO, 4 GUYS GET INTO THIS BIG
CIRCLE FILLED WITH FARGANS
AND THROW THESE MELONS
BACK AND FORTH.
THEY USE STICKS WITH
METAL BASKETS AT THE END.
DO YOU PLAY MONKEY IN THE MIDDLE
ON DENOBULA?
PHLOX: I DON'T BELIEVE SO.
TRAVIS: ANYWAY, AFTER A WHILE,
THE FARGANS START FIGURING OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON--
TUCKER: GOT A MINUTE, DOC?
PHLOX: ARE YOU NOT
FEELING WELL, COMMANDER?
TUCKER: NO, I--I'M FINE.
I JUST, UH, I NEED TO TALK
TO YOU FOR A MINUTE.
PHLOX: BY ALL MEANS.
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
TUCKER: UH, ACTUALLY,
I WAS KIND OF HOPING
TO TALK TO YOU ALONE.
PHLOX: AH. I THINK
WE'RE ABOUT DONE HERE.
IT WOULD BE BEST IF YOU
AVOIDED FARGANS FOR A FEW DAYS.
TRAVIS: THANKS, DOC.
HEH HEH.
COMMANDER.
TUCKER: SEE YOU, TRAVIS.
MALCOLM SAID THIS
WAS A BAD IDEA, BUT...
I--I THINK IT'S
THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
PHLOX: WHAT'S THAT?
TUCKER: FEEZAL...
I MEAN MRS. PHLOX...
IS A LOVELY WOMAN.
AND--AND SHE'S VERY SMART.
SHE KNOWS MORE
ABOUT QUANTUM OPTICS
THAN ANYONE I'VE EVER MET.
PHLOX: SHE IS REMARKABLE.
TUCKER: REMARKABLE.
YEAH, SHE SURE IS.
PHLOX: WAS THERE SOMETHING ELSE?
TUCKER: YEAH, THERE IS.
YOU GOT TO UNDERSTAND,
I'VE BEEN A PERFECT GENTLEMAN.
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING'S HAPPENED.
SHE'S TRYING TO...
SHE'S--SHE'S, UM...
MAKING ADVANCES,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
PHLOX: SEXUAL ADVANCES?
TUCKER: I'M AFRAID SO.
PHLOX: HAS SHE OFFERED TO
GIVE YOU A ROSE-PETAL BATH?
TUCKER:
NO, NO, NO, NOTHING LIKE THAT.
PHLOX: OH, ANY MAN
WOULD BE A FOOL TO IGNORE
THE ROMANTIC OVERTURES OF
A HEALTHY DENOBULAN WOMAN.
DON'T YOU FIND HER ATTRACTIVE?
TUCKER: OH, SURE.
I MEAN, NO, SHE'S YOUR WIFE.
PHLOX: WHAT DOES THAT
HAVE TO DO WITH IT?
TUCKER: SHE'S YOUR WIFE.
PHLOX: OH, NONSENSE. NONSENSE.
YOU'RE TOO CONCERNED
WITH HUMAN MORALITY.
I THOUGHT YOU WANTED TO
LEARN ABOUT, UH, NEW CULTURES.
ISN'T THAT WHY YOU
JOINED STARFLEET?
TUCKER: WHY, OF COURSE IT IS.
BUT I WAS BROUGHT UP BELIEVING
YOU DON'T PLAY AROUND
WITH ANOTHER MAN'S WIFE.
I DON'T THINK I'M EVER
GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ABOUT THAT.
PHLOX: AS YOU WISH. YOUR LOSS.
[DOOR CHIMES]
T'POL: COME IN.
LIEUTENANT REED TOLD ME
YOU WENT TO THE SURFACE.
ARCHER: I SPOKE TO DR. ORATT.
I DIDN'T TELL YOU
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT YOU
TO TRY AND TALK ME OUT OF IT.
T'POL:
I ASSUME YOU WERE UNSUCCESSFUL.
ARCHER: NOT EXACTLY.
BEFORE I LEFT,
I GOT THE MEDICAL PROTOCOLS
FROM HOSHI.
IT SEEMS THEY OWE YOU A HEARING.
T'POL: THEY'LL NEVER AGREE.
ARCHER: THEY ALREADY DID.
T'POL: I HAVE NO INTEREST IN
CHALLENGING THEIR DECISION.
ARCHER: IF YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
DEFEND YOURSELF,
THE LEAST YOU CAN DO
IS SPEAK FOR THIS MINORITY
YOU'RE SO EAGER TO PROTECT.
YOU SAID YOU DIDN'T WANT
TO CONDONE
THE ATTITUDE OF THESE DOCTORS.
YOUR SILENCE WOULD DO JUST THAT.
T'POL: YOU NEED TO UNDERSTAND...
I WON'T TELL THEM
HOW I GOT THE DISEASE.
ARCHER: I'LL GO ALONG WITH THAT.
I PROMISE.
BUT YOU'VE GOT TO UNDERSTAND,
I'M NOT GONNA GIVE YOU UP
WITHOUT A FIGHT.
STROM: THE FACT THAT
SHE HAS PA'NAR SYNDROME
IS NOT THE REASON
SHE'S BEING RECALLED.
ARCHER: NO. IT HAS TO DO
WITH HOW SHE GOT INFECTED.
A MIND-MELD OVER A YEAR AGO.
STROM: WHEN IT TOOK PLACE
IS NOT PERTINENT.
ARCHER: SO WHAT YOU'RE SAYING
IS THAT IF A VULCAN--
EVEN AN OFFICER
IN THE SCIENCE DIRECTORATE--
ENGAGES IN THIS EXCHANGE
OF THOUGHTS AND MEMORIES,
THEY'RE CONDEMNED FOR IT?
ORATT:
AS YOU'VE BEEN TOLD, CAPTAIN,
MIND-MELDS ARE PRACTICED
BY A SUBCULTURE--
VULCANS WHO HAVE ELECTED
TO CONDUCT THEMSELVES
IN AN UNACCEPTABLE MANNER.
T'POL: THEY HAVEN'T ELECTED
TO DO ANYTHING.
THEY'RE BORN WITH THIS ABILITY.
STROM: EXACTLY.
THEY'RE GENETIC ABERRATIONS
WHO PREY ON PEOPLE LIKE YOU,
PEOPLE FOOLISH ENOUGH
TO EXPERIMENT
WITH ABHORRENT BEHAVIOR.
ARCHER:
"YOU HUMANS ARE TOO VOLATILE,
TOO IRRATIONAL,
TOO NARROW-MINDED."
THAT'S WHAT I HEARD FOR
YEARS FROM EVERY VULCAN I MET.
BUT WE DON'T
HOLD A CANDLE TO YOU
WHEN IT COMES
TO "NARROW-MINDED."
WE GOT RID OF BIGOTRY
NEARLY A CENTURY AGO.
WE'RE NOT AFRAID OF DIVERSITY.
WE DON'T PERSECUTE IT.
WE EMBRACE IT.
IF YOU CALL YOURSELVES
ENLIGHTENED,
YOU HAVE TO ACCEPT PEOPLE
WHO ARE DIFFERENT THAN YOU ARE.
STROM: THIS IS POINTLESS.
OUR CULTURE IS GOVERNED
BY RULES.
WE'RE NOT ABOUT TO IGNORE THEM.
T'POL: THERE ARE
NO RULES TELLING YOU
TO OPPRESS MINORITIES.
STROM: YOU'D RATHER LET
THEM SPREAD THEIR INFECTIONS.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHY
YOU'RE BEING RECALLED.
T'POL: NO, I'M BEING RECALLED
BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID
OF ANYTHING
THAT DOESN'T CONFORM TO YOUR
IDEA OF ACCEPTABLE BEHAVIOR.
STROM: UNFORTUNATELY, YOU DON'T
KNOW WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THE DECISION'S BEEN MADE.
WE SHOULD END THIS INQUIRY.
YURIS: SHE KNOWS EXACTLY
WHAT SHE'S TALKING ABOUT.
ORATT: ARE YOU QUESTIONING
OUR JUDGMENT?
YURIS:
THERE IS NOTHING ABHORRENT
ABOUT THE WAY WE LEAD OUR LIVES.
STROM: WE?
YURIS: THERE IS NO
SIMPLE DEFINITION OF INTIMACY.
THOSE OF US CAPABLE
OF MIND-MELDS
ARE NO DIFFERENT THAN YOU ARE.
ORATT: YOU REALIZE
THAT YOU'RE JEOPARDIZING
YOUR REPUTATION, YOUR CAREER.
YURIS: WE SHARE
OUR THOUGHTS DIFFERENTLY.
WE SHOULDN'T BE PUNISHED
FOR THAT.
ORATT: THE HIGH COMMAND
WILL DETERMINE
WHETHER YOU SHOULD
BE PUNISHED--BOTH OF YOU.
YURIS: SHE'S
NOT GUILTY OF ANYTHING.
SHE WAS VIOLATED.
T'POL: YOU GAVE ME YOUR WORD.
YURIS: THE MIND-MELD WAS
PERFORMED AGAINST HER WILL.
ORATT: CAN YOU VERIFY THIS?
T'POL: WHY? SO YOU CAN
PERPETUATE YOUR DOUBLE STANDARD?
CONDEMN THE INFECTED
WHEN THEY MELD BY CHOICE
AND SYMPATHIZE WITH THEM
WHEN THEY DON'T?
ORATT: WHAT DO YOU KNOW
OF THIS, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: SEEMS MY SCIENCE OFFICER
DOESN'T WANT TO DISCUSS IT.
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
YURIS: SHE TOLD ME HERSELF.
SHE MADE ME PROMISE
TO STAY SILENT. I'M SORRY.
I HAD TO TELL THEM THE TRUTH.
YOU SHOULD DO THE SAME.
T'POL: I HAVE NOTHING
TO SAY TO THEM.
PHLOX: FEEZAL TELLS ME
IT CAN BE QUITE TEMPERAMENTAL.
TUCKER:
I THINK I'VE GOT IT FIGURED OUT.
JUST LET ME KNOW
WHEN IT STARTS ACTING UP.
HAVE YOU GOT
THE ACTIVATION SEQUENCE DOWN?
PHLOX: MY BELOVED.
[BOTH SNIFF]
BOTH: MM.
PHLOX: I CERTAINLY HOPE
IT'S NOT ANOTHER 4 YEARS
UNTIL I SEE YOU AGAIN.
FEEZAL: SO DO I.
NOW, REMEMBER, YOUR OTHER WIVES
ARE ANXIOUS TO SEE YOU, TOO.
PHLOX:
COMMANDER TUCKER ASSURES ME
HE'LL KEEP
YOUR BEAUTIFUL MICROSCOPE
IN PERFECT RUNNING ORDER.
FEEZAL: AS HIS DOCTOR, I HOPE
YOU'LL KEEP COMMANDER TUCKER
IN PERFECT RUNNING ORDER.
PERHAPS THAT WILL MOTIVATE ME
TO VISIT MORE OFTEN.
PHLOX: MM. IT'S A SHAME
YOU TWO DIDN'T
GET TO, UH,
KNOW EACH OTHER BETTER.
TUCKER: WELL, I'VE GOT TO
GET BACK TO MY WARP ENGINE.
THE PLASMA'S RUNNING
A LITTLE HOT.
FEEZAL: I KNOW HOW IT FEELS.
TUCKER: PLEASURE MEETING YOU.
PHLOX: HUMANS.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
DR. YURIS HAS BEEN SUSPENDED.
T'POL: THAT WAS TO BE EXPECTED.
ARCHER: THEY OFFERED HIM
A HEARING, BUT HE REFUSED.
ORATT SAID
HE'LL LOSE HIS STANDING
WITH THE MEDICAL EXCHANGE
WHEN THEY GET BACK TO VULCAN.
T'POL: ALSO TO BE EXPECTED.
ARCHER: ONE GOOD THING
DID COME OUT OF THIS.
THEY BELIEVED HIM WHEN
HE SAID YOU WERE FORCED.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE RECALLED.
T'POL: WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
I'LL BE CONTACTING
THE HIGH COMMAND.
I DON'T INTEND TO LET YURIS BE
DISMISSED WITHOUT A FIGHT.
ARCHER: PERMISSION GRANTED.
I KNOW YOU MUST
BE VERY DISAPPOINTED
THAT HE BROKE
HIS PROMISE TO YOU.
BUT ON A SELFISH NOTE,
I'M GLAD HE DID.
I DIDN'T WANT TO LOSE YOU.
T'POL: MAYBE THIS INCIDENT
WILL ENCOURAGE OTHERS
TO SPEAK OUT.
ARCHER: WELL, LET'S HOPE SO.