[ EXPLOSIONS, WEAPONS FIRE ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ GROANING ]
[ SIGHS ]
ALIEN: REPORT.
ALIEN 2:
THE IMPERIAL GUARD WILL DIE AT
THEIR POSTS BEFORE THEY WILL --
ALIEN: I KNOW MY MEN
ARE WILLING TO DIE.
I WANT TO HEAR THEIR CHANCES
OF SURVIVING.
ALIEN 2: WE'RE HOLDING
OUR POSITIONS FOR NOW,
BUT THE ENEMY HAS DEPLOYED
NEW UNITS HERE AND HERE.
ALIEN: THEY'RE LOOKING
FOR A WEAKNESS.
ALIEN 2: THEY MAY HAVE FOUND IT.
WE'VE TAKEN MORE CASUALTIES.
ALIEN: I'VE RECEIVED
A COMMUNIQUE.
THE VULCANS WANT TO DISCUSS
TERMS FOR A CEASE-FIRE.
ALIEN: HAVE YOU EVER
KNOWN A VULCAN
WHO WOULDN'T LIE
TO GET WHAT HE WANTED?
ALIEN: THERE IS
ANOTHER OPTION --
SOMEONE I'VE DEALT WITH --
A PINK-SKIN.
HE'S PROVEN TO BE
QUITE EVEN-HANDED
IN DEALING WITH VULCANS.
HIS NAME IS ARCHER.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
YOU'RE SURE HE WANTS ME?
AMBASSADOR SOVAL SAID
YOUR PRESENCE IS CRUCIAL
TO RESOLVING THE CRISIS.
WHAT'S THIS PLANET CALLED AGAIN?
THE VULCAN NAME IS PAAN MOKAR.
THE ANDORIANS CALL IT WEYTAHN.
IT'S ON THE FRONTIER
BETWEEN THEIR SYSTEMS.
BOTH SIDES CLAIM
IT BELONGS TO THEM.
THEY'VE NEARLY GONE
TO WAR OVER IT TWICE
IN THE PAST CENTURY.
HOW DO THEY EXPECT ME
TO HELP SETTLE A CONFLICT
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO RESOLVE IN 100 YEARS?
SOVAL SAYS YOU'LL BE
FULLY BRIEFED WHEN YOU ARRIVE.
JONATHAN,
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
THE VULCANS HAVE ASKED
FOR OUR HELP.
YOU'RE THE CLOSEST THING
WE HAVE
TO AN AMBASSADOR OUT THERE.
YOU KNOW HOW IMPORTANT
THIS COULD BE.
WE'LL GET THERE
AS FAST AS WE CAN.
I DON'T LIKE
PUSHING THE ENGINES THIS HARD.
THE INJECTORS ARE RUNNING
AT 110%.
T'POL: THEY'RE RATED FOR 120%.
TUCKER: AND MY UNDERWEAR
IS FLAME-RETARDANT.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN I'M
GONNA LIGHT MYSELF ON
FIRE TO PROVE IT.
ARCHER: I THINK WE'LL MAKE IT
IN ONE PIECE, TRIP.
I'VE BEEN READING ABOUT PAAN
MOKAR IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
IT DOESN'T SAY A LOT.
CLASS-D, NOT MUCH BIGGER
THAN EARTH'S MOON.
CLAIMED BY THE VULCANS IN 2097.
TUCKER: CLASS-D?
THAT'S UNINHABITABLE.
WHY ARE YOU FIGHTING OVER IT?
T'POL: WHEN THE ANDORIANS
FIRST ARRIVED A CENTURY AGO,
THEY BEGAN
TO TERRAFORM THE PLANET.
ONCE AN ATMOSPHERE
WAS DEVELOPED,
THEY ESTABLISHED A SETTLEMENT.
ARCHER: IF IT WAS
UNCLAIMED AT THE TIME,
WHY WOULD THERE BE A PROBLEM?
T'POL: ITS SOLE VALUE IS
ITS STRATEGIC LOCATION
NEAR VULCAN SPACE.
ARCHER: THEY WERE SETTING UP
A MILITARY BASE?
T'POL: IT WAS THE ONLY
LOGICAL CONCLUSION.
TUCKER: WAS THERE ANY EVIDENCE?
T'POL: HOW MUCH EVIDENCE
WOULD YOU NEED
IF THE KLINGONS DECIDED
TO SET UP A COLONY ON PLUTO?
TUCKER: THAT'S NOT
THE SAME THING.
T'POL: THE ANDORIANS REFUSED
TO LET THE HIGH COMMAND
INSPECT THE COLONY,
SO THEY ANNEXED PAAN MOKAR
TO PROTECT THEIR TERRITORY.
ARCHER: WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE ANDORIAN COLONISTS?
T'POL: THEY WERE REMOVED.
TUCKER: BY FORCE.
T'POL: THEY LEFT THE
HIGH COMMAND LITTLE CHOICE.
A SURVEILLANCE SATELLITE
WAS PUT INTO ORBIT
TO MONITOR THE AGREEMENT.
THE PLANET'S BEEN DESERTED
FOR NEARLY A CENTURY.
ARCHER: UNTIL NOW.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
IN THE 3 DAYS IT'S TAKEN US
TO REACH PAAN MOKAR,
THE SITUATION HAS GROWN
CONSIDERABLY MORE TENSE.
TUCKER: UNBELIEVABLE.
I DAMN NEAR BURN UP
THE WARP REACTOR GETTING HERE,
AND THEY MAKE US WAIT.
ARCHER:
WELCOME ABOARD, AMBASSADOR.
SOVAL: THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS SUBCOMMANDER MUROC.
ARCHER:
T'POL HAS BEEN FILLING ME IN
ON THE SITUATION HERE,
BUT I STILL HAVE
A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
SOVAL:
IF YOU DON'T MIND, CAPTAIN,
I HAVE A QUESTION OF MY OWN.
WHY WOULD AN OFFICER
OF THE ANDORIAN IMPERIAL GUARD
PERSONALLY REQUEST
YOUR INVOLVEMENT?
[ SIGHS ]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I WAS TOLD YOU ASKED FOR ME.
I'M INVOLVED
IN EXTREMELY DIFFICULT
AND DANGEROUS NEGOTIATIONS.
I DON'T CONSIDER
YOUR PRESENCE HERE AN ASSET.
IF THAT'S HOW YOU FEEL,
WE'LL GLADLY CONTINUE
WITH OUR MISSION.
6 DAYS AGO, AN ANDORIAN
REGIMENTAL COMMANDER NAMED SHRAN
LANDED A FORCE ON PAAN MOKAR
AND OCCUPIED THE SETTLEMENT.
ARCHER: SHRAN.
SOVAL: NATURALLY, WE ATTEMPTED
TO ENFORCE THE TREATY OF 2097.
NATURALLY.
WE'VE REGAINED
CONTROL OF HALF THE COLONY,
BUT TWO DOZEN VULCANS
HAVE BEEN WOUNDED,
AND 3 HAVE BEEN
TAKEN HOSTAGE.
SOVAL: SHRAN HAS AGREED
TO DISCUSS TERMS
FOR THEIR SAFE RETURN,
BUT ONLY IF YOU ACT
AS MEDIATOR.
FOR SOME REASON,
HE FINDS YOU TRUSTWORTHY.
YOU'RE ASKING FOR MY HELP?
YES, CAPTAIN,
I'M ASKING FOR YOUR HELP.
ARCHER: I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
SOVAL: FORGIVE MY CANDOR,
BUT THAT'S HARDLY REASSURING.
THE LAST TIME YOU DEALT
WITH THE ANDORIANS,
A VULCAN INTELLIGENCE SITE
WAS COMPROMISED
AND A PRICELESS MONASTERY
DESTROYED.
SUBCOMMANDER MUROC
WILL ACCOMPANY YOU
TO REPRESENT OUR INTERESTS.
ARCHER: OBVIOUSLY, I'M HERE
AT THE REQUEST OF THE ANDORIANS.
SHRAN BELIEVES HE CAN TRUST ME.
I DON'T INTEND
TO PROVE HIM WRONG
BY GOING DOWN THERE WITH
A VULCAN OFFICER IN TOW.
IF YOU INSIST I BRING
A VULCAN ALONG,
I'LL TAKE THE ONE
I KNOW I CAN TRUST.
ARCHER: YOU WANTED
TO SEE ME, DOC?
PHLOX: YES.
THIS PLANET IS HOME
TO A RATHER PERNICIOUS
MUTAGENIC PATHOGEN,
AND I'LL NEED TO BOMBARD
YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM
WITH ANALEPTIC RADIATION
TO PROTECT YOU
WHILE YOU'RE ON THE SURFACE.
ARCHER: BOMBARD?
PHLOX: IT'S QUITE PAINLESS,
I ASSURE YOU.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT T'POL?
PHLOX: VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY ISN'T
AFFECTED BY THE PATHOGEN.
SHALL WE?
THIS SHOULD ONLY TAKE A MOMENT.
IF I MAY ASK,
HOW DID YOUR FIRST MEETING
WITH THE VULCANS GO?
ARCHER: WARM AND FRIENDLY
AS EVER.
PHLOX: IRONIC.
THEY WEREN'T OVERLY ENTHUSIASTIC
ABOUT YOU
TAKING COMMAND OF ENTERPRISE
IN THE FIRST PLACE,
AND NOW YOUR PRESENCE IS CRUCIAL
TO THEIR INTERESTS.
ARCHER: IT'S CRUCIAL
TO OURS, TOO.
MAYBE WE'RE NOT OUT HERE
TO JUST SCAN COMETS
AND MEET NEW SPECIES.
MAYBE WE'RE OUT HERE
TO PROVE THAT HUMANITY'S READY
TO JOIN A MUCH LARGER COMMUNITY.
I INTEND TO DO THAT...
WHETHER THE VULCANS
LIKE IT OR NOT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
PHLOX: ALL FINISHED.
CAPTAIN,
I SERVED AS A MEDIC
IN THE DENOBULAN INFANTRY.
IF I LEARNED ANYTHING
FROM THAT EXPERIENCE,
IT'S THAT BATTLEFIELDS
ARE UNPREDICTABLE PLACES,
EVEN UNDER A FLAG OF TRUCE.
BE CAREFUL.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
ARCHER: WE'VE LOST
THE NAVIGATIONAL SENSORS.
AND THE COM.
T'POL: IT'S THE ANDORIAN
JAMMING SIGNAL.
I'M ENTERING THE LANDING
COORDINATES THEY GAVE US.
ARCHER: LET'S HOPE
THEY'RE ACCURATE.
DID YOU HAVE A CHANCE TO READ
THE TERRITORIAL COMPROMISE?
I GLANCED AT IT.
THE COMPROMISE IS AT THE HEART
OF THIS DISPUTE.
IT'S WORTH YOUR ATTENTION.
ARCHER: IT'S 1,200 PAGES LONG.
T'POL: DID YOU GLANCE AT
ANY OF THE OTHER MATERIALS
I SENT TO YOUR QUARTERS?
V'LAR'S TREATISE
ON NEGOTIATING TACTICS
IS THE DEFINITIVE TEXT
ON THE SUBJECT.
ARCHER: I GOT ALL OF IT --
V'LAR'S TREATISE,
THE REVISED
INTERSYSTEM AGREEMENT,
THE HIGH COMMAND BRIEFING
ON THE BORDER INCURSIONS
OF 2112.
I WAS UP TILL 2:00 A.M.
T'POL: GLANCING.
[ ARCHER SIGHS ]
ARE YOU TRYING
TO TELL ME SOMETHING?
THAT MAYBE I'M NOT
PREPARED FOR THIS?
AMBASSADOR SOVAL CLEARLY
BELIEVES YOU'LL FAIL.
I WAS HOPING
SOME ADVANCE PREPARATION
WOULD HELP YOU PROVE HIM WRONG.
ARCHER: THANKS.
BUT I DOUBT I'M GOING
TO IMPRESS SHRAN
BY QUOTING VULCAN TREATIES.
I ASSUME YOU HAVE A STRATEGY?
ARCHER: THE FIRST THING
IS TO CONVINCE SHRAN
THAT HE CAN TRUST ME.
T'POL: AND THEN?
ARCHER: WE'RE JUST GONNA
HAVE TO PLAY IT BY EAR.
[ EXPLOSIONS, WEAPONS FIRE ]
ARCHER: ARE YOU SURE THESE
ARE THE COORDINATES?
T'POL: YES.
ALIEN: DON'T MOVE, VULCAN.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WE'RE NOT ARMED.
[ WEAPONS CHARGING ]
ARCHER: I'M CAPTAIN
JONATHAN ARCHER.
I'M HERE TO SEE COMMANDER SHRAN.
HE'S EXPECTING YOU
WITHOUT A VULCAN ESCORT.
ARCHER: I WASN'T
TOLD TO COME ALONE.
THIS IS MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
SHE HELPED EXPOSE
THE VULCAN LISTENING POST
AT P'JEM.
I THOUGHT SHRAN MIGHT
ENJOY SEEING HER AGAIN.
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING
IN DISTANCE ]
ARCHER: I IMAGINED MY FIRST
DIPLOMATIC MISSION
WOULD INVOLVE SITTING
AROUND A BIG TABLE,
TOASTING WITH CHAMPAGNE,
SIGNING THINGS
WITH LOTS OF PENS.
THE PINK-SKIN SENSE OF HUMOR.
ALIEN: MY APOLOGIES
FOR THE SECURITY PRECAUTIONS.
ALIEN 2: WE CAN
NEVER BE TOO VIGILANT
WHEN IT COMES TO VULCANS.
ARCHER: THEY SAY
THE SAME THING ABOUT YOU.
I'M SURE THEY DO.
WE'RE AGGRESSIVE, ILLOGICAL.
ARCHER: PROVE THEM WRONG.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE,
CAPTAIN --
TO HELP US DO JUST THAT.
I'VE DEALT WITH THE VULCANS
TWICE BEFORE
WHERE YOU WERE INVOLVED.
BOTH TIMES, YOU HANDLED
THE SITUATION WITHOUT PREJUDICE.
I HOPE I CAN HELP AGAIN.
BUT THE FIRST THING I NEED
IS TO SEE THE HOSTAGES.
ALIEN 2: HOSTAGES?
CRIMINALS TAKE HOSTAGES.
KIDNAPPERS LOOKING FOR RANSOM
TAKE HOSTAGES.
I ASSUME YOU'RE REFERRING
TO THE ENEMY SOLDIERS
WE CAPTURED.
THE VULCANS WANT TO
KNOW THEY'RE ALL RIGHT.
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN HARMED.
ARCHER: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
ALIEN:
WHEN THEY ATTACKED US, TWO
OF MY MEN WERE BADLY WOUNDED.
THEY'RE LUCKY
WE DIDN'T KILL THEM.
YOU PROVOKED THIS SITUATION
WHEN YOU VIOLATED
THE TERRITORIAL COMPROMISE.
ALIEN: ONLY A VULCAN COULD CALL
A HUNDRED YEARS OF OPPRESSION
A COMPROMISE.
YOU ANNEXED A PLANET
THAT BELONGS TO US,
HERDED OUR PEOPLE
INTO REFUGEE CAMPS.
T'POL: AFTER YOU SET UP
A MILITARY OUTPOST HERE.
ALIEN: AS YOU CAN SEE, CAPTAIN,
EVEN AFTER A HUNDRED YEARS,
THIS SITUATION STILL EVOKES
ANGER ON BOTH SIDES.
WE WILL RELEASE OUR PRISONERS
ON THE FOLLOWING CONDITIONS --
IMMEDIATE WITHDRAWAL
OF ALL VULCAN MILITARY FORCES,
THE SO-CALLED COMPROMISE
IS TO BE RESCINDED,
AND THE VULCANS MUST CONCEDE
IRREVOCABLE SOVEREIGNTY
OF WEYTAHN TO ANDORIA.
ARCHER: YOU DON'T EXPECT THEM
TO AGREE TO ALL THAT.
I TOLD YOU,
HE'S A PUPPET OF THE VULCANS.
ARCHER: FOR THE RECORD,
THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
DOESN'T LIKE ME VERY MUCH,
AND FRANKLY,
THE FEELING IS MUTUAL.
IF ALL YOU NEED IS SOMEONE
TO DELIVER YOUR LIST OF DEMANDS,
FIND SOMEBODY ELSE.
I'VE GOT OTHER THINGS TO DO.
ALIEN: THE VULCANS ALWAYS SAY
THEY'RE READY TO TALK,
BUT IT AMOUNTS TO NOTHING --
TREATY NEGOTIATIONS
THAT DRAG ON FOR YEARS.
I WANT TO SPEAK TO SOVAL --
SOMEBODY WHO CAN DEAL
WITH THE SITUATION
WITHOUT HAVING TO CHECK
WITH HIS SUPERIORS.
ARCHER: I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
ALIEN: HERE!
ON MY TERMS.
ARCHER: THAT MIGHT BE
A LITTLE DIFFICULT.
THIS IS POINTLESS.
ARCHER: BUT NOT IMPOSSIBLE.
THE THING IS, HE'S GOING TO WANT
SOMETHING IN RETURN.
ALIEN: HAVEN'T THEY ALREADY
TAKEN ENOUGH?
ARCHER: I'M TALKING
ABOUT A GESTURE --
SOMETHING TO SHOW
YOU'RE SERIOUS.
I CAME DOWN HERE
TO SEE ABOUT THE HOSTAGES.
WHY DON'T YOU LET THEM GO?
AND GIVE AWAY
OUR ONLY ADVANTAGE?
NO.
ARCHER: RELEASE
TWO OF THEM, THEN.
KEEP THE OTHER ONE UNTIL
AFTER YOU'VE MET WITH SOVAL.
ALIEN: ONE. AS A SHOW
OF OUR GOOD FAITH.
UNACCEPTABLE.
YOU GOT ONE OF YOUR MEN BACK.
SOVAL: AND IN EXCHANGE,
YOU'LL DELIVER ME
INTO THEIR HANDS?
I'M SURE THE ANDORIANS
WERE IMPRESSED WITH YOUR
NEGOTIATING SKILLS.
ARCHER: THEY WANT TO
TALK TO YOU, NOT KIDNAP YOU.
SOVAL: IF I AGREE TO A MEETING,
IT SIMPLY LEGITIMIZES
THEIR POSITION.
ARCHER: AND IF YOU DON'T,
THESE NEGOTIATIONS END
BEFORE THEY BEGIN.
MUROC: THAT MAY HAPPEN
SOONER THAN YOU REALIZE.
WHILE YOU WERE ON THE SURFACE,
WE DETECTED 3 ANDORIAN
VESSELS APPROACHING.
THEY'LL BE HERE IN LESS
THAN 5 HOURS.
SOVAL: THEY PROBABLY INTEND
TO RESUPPLY THEIR TROOPS
ON THE SURFACE.
WE WON'T ALLOW THAT.
T'POL: ENGAGING
AN ANDORIAN VESSEL
COULD BE CONSTRUED
AS AN ACT OF WAR.
SOVAL: THAT WILL
BE THEIR DECISION.
BOTH SIDES ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENS HERE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND THE
COMPLEXITIES OF THIS SITUATION.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
AMBASSADOR,
WHY DID YOU AGREE
TO LET ME GO DOWN THERE
IF YOU WON'T LISTEN
TO MY ADVICE?
I DIDN'T REQUEST YOUR HELP,
CAPTAIN,
AND I DON'T FEEL OBLIGED
TO ACCEPT IT.
YOU CLAIM THE ANDORIANS
ARE INFLEXIBLE.
AT LEAST THEY'RE WILLING
TO SIT DOWN AND TALK.
THE BALL'S IN YOUR COURT NOW.
T'POL: IT'S A HUMAN EXPRESSION.
IT MEANS THE NEXT MOVE IS YOURS.
MUROC: THIS ISN'T WISE.
THE COLONY HASN'T BEEN SECURED.
SOVAL: DIDN'T YOU
HEAR THE CAPTAIN?
THE BALL IS IN OUR COURT.
TUCKER: I DON'T LIKE THIS.
WITH ALL THE INTERFERENCE,
YOU WON'T BE ABLE
TO CONTACT THE SHIP
IF SOMETHING GOES WRONG.
ARCHER: THEY'RE EXPECTING US.
WE'LL BE FINE.
TUCKER: THOSE ANDORIAN SHIPS'LL
BE HERE IN 4 HOURS.
ARCHER: I PLAN ON BEING BACK
LONG BEFORE THEN.
TUCKER: T'POL SAID THAT
TERRITORIAL COMPROMISE
THEY WERE TALKING ABOUT
TOOK 8 YEARS TO WORK OUT.
ARCHER: I'LL TRY TO
SPEED THINGS UP THIS TIME.
ALIEN: BRING THEM HERE
AS SOON AS THEY LAND,
AND TREAT THE VULCAN
WITH RESPECT.
ALIEN 2: YES, SIR.
IF I MAY SPEAK?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO SAY.
WE DISCOVERED THIS PLANET.
WE MADE IT LIVABLE.
IT BELONGS TO US.
DON'T WORRY,
IT'LL BE OURS AGAIN.
HOW? BY TALKING?
WE'VE BEEN TRYING THAT
FOR A HUNDRED YEARS,
AND IT'S GOTTEN US NOWHERE.
THEY STALL AND LIE
AND MAKE PROMISES
THEY NEVER INTEND TO KEEP.
WE CAME HERE TO FIGHT.
WHY BACK DOWN NOW?
ALIEN: I'M WILLING TO
GIVE ARCHER ANOTHER CHANCE.
ALIEN 2: YOU PUT TOO MUCH FAITH
IN THESE PINK-SKINS.
WE DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THEM
EXCEPT THAT THEY'RE FRIENDS
OF THE VULCANS.
ALIEN: NOT ALWAYS.
I'VE SEEN THAT FOR MYSELF.
ALIEN 2: IF WE ATTACK NOW,
WE CAN HAVE THE VULCANS
ON THE DEFENSIVE
BEFORE OUR SHIPS ARRIVE.
ALIEN: YOUR RECOMMENDATION
IS NOTED.
ALIEN 2: OUR TROOPS ARE READY.
THERE'S NO REASON TO WAIT.
ALIEN: ENOUGH!
I VALUE YOUR OPINION,
TARAH,
BUT THAT DOES NOT ALLOW YOU
TO QUESTION MY COMMANDS.
DISMISSED.
ARCHER: THEY'LL SEND SOME
SOLDIERS TO MEET US.
I'M AFRAID
THEY'LL WANT TO BLINDFOLD YOU.
IT'S JUST A SECURITY PRECAUTION.
SOVAL: THANK YOU
FOR THE REASSURANCE.
NOW, IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'LL NEED A FEW MOMENTS OF
SILENCE TO PREPARE MYSELF.
ARCHER: OF COURSE.
[ EXPLOSION ]
ARCHER: T'POL?
T'POL: WEAPONS FIRE.
I CAN'T PINPOINT THE SOURCE.
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
T'POL: WE'RE STILL WITHIN
THEIR JAMMING RANGE.
I SUGGEST WE CANCEL
THE NEGOTIATIONS
AND RETURN TO YOUR SHIP.
ARCHER: FOR ONCE,
WE'RE IN FULL AGREEMENT.
T'POL: DIRECT HIT
TO OUR STARBOARD ENGINE.
MAIN POWER'S OFFLINE.
NOW YOU SEE WHO YOU'RE
DEALING WITH, CAPTAIN?
IF YOU DON'T MIND, AMBASSADOR --
T'POL: WE'RE LOSING ALTITUDE.
200 METERS.
ARCHER: I'M GONNA BRING US IN
ON THRUSTERS.
100 METERS.
50.
WE NEED TO REDUCE OUR SPEED.
ARCHER: THE GROUND IS GOING
TO DO THAT FOR US.
BRACE YOURSELVES.
ARCHER: ANY IDEA WHERE WE ARE?
SOVAL: THE SOUTHEAST QUADRANT.
NEAR THE OLD SPACEPORT.
I TOLD YOU I NEGOTIATED
THE LAST ACCORD.
I ALSO SERVED HERE.
T'POL: YOU WERE WITH
THE OCCUPATION FORCE?
SOVAL: AS AN INTELLIGENCE
OFFICER, A LONG TIME AGO.
OUR CURRENT DEPLOYMENT
HAS A BASE
OF OPERATIONS THAT WAY
ABOUT 2 1/2 KILOMETERS.
I APPRECIATE YOUR HELP,
AMBASSADOR,
BUT WE'RE LOOKING
FOR THE ANDORIANS.
SOVAL: CIRCUMSTANCES
HAVE ALTERED OUR PLANS.
ARCHER: I GAVE MY WORD TO SHRAN.
I INTEND TO KEEP IT.
[ WEAPONS FIRE IN DISTANCE ]
SOVAL: SHRAN JUST
TRIED TO KILL US.
ARCHER: WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
SOVAL:
I SUPPOSE YOU THINK OUR TROOPS
ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS?
SENSORS AND COMMUNICATIONS
ARE OFFLINE.
THERE'S WEAPONS FIRE
FLYING ALL OVER THE PLACE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
SOVAL: ARE YOU THAT NAIVE?
SHRAN IS USING YOU.
ARCHER: THIS IS A MAN
WHO COULDN'T SLEEP
BECAUSE HE THOUGHT
HE OWED ME SOMETHING.
I DON'T BELIEVE HE ASKED ME
TO COME A DOZEN LIGHT-YEARS
JUST SO I COULD
LEAD YOU INTO A TRAP.
AND RIGHT NOW,
IT SEEMS
LIKE THE BEST THING TO DO
IS TO GET
A CEASE FIRE IN PLACE.
THE ANDORIANS WON'T
AGREE TO THAT
UNTIL THEY TALK TO YOU
IN PERSON.
I MANAGED TO KEEP US ON COURSE
MOST OF THE WAY IN.
WE CAN'T BE MORE
THAN A KILOMETER
FROM SHRAN'S
LANDING COORDINATES.
TUCKER: HOW WOULD YOU KNOW?
WE CAN'T PICK UP ANYTHING
THROUGH THE INTERFERENCE.
OUR SCANNERS ARE
MORE SOPHISTICATED THAN YOURS.
WE DETECTED WEAPONS FIRE
COMING FROM THE SURFACE.
THEN YOUR SHUTTLE
APPEARED TO MAKE
AN EMERGENCY LANDING
SOMEWHERE IN THE COLONY.
WHERE?
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO PINPOINT THEIR LANDING SITE,
BUT OUR UNITS ON THE GROUND
ARE ALREADY SEARCHING.
THE HIGH COMMAND
INSTRUCTED ME TO TAKE STEPS
TO RECOVER AMBASSADOR SOVAL.
AND OUR OFFICERS?
OF COURSE.
WE WANT TO BE INVOLVED
IN ANY RESCUE OPERATION.
WE HAVE MORE EXPERIENCE
IN THESE MATTERS.
I KNOW -- I ONCE SAW
ONE OF YOUR COMMANDO UNITS
BLAST THE HELL
OUT OF A REBEL COMPOUND
DURING A RESCUE MISSION.
WE WON'T ALLOW
THIS PROVOCATION TO CONTINUE.
YOU DON'T EVEN
KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
IT'S A GOOD IDEA
TO GO DOWN THERE, GUNS BLAZING?
OUR RESPONSE
WILL BE APPROPRIATE.
I'LL KEEP YOU INFORMED,
COMMANDER.
ANY LUCK?
I'M TRYING, SIR,
BUT IF THE VULCANS
CAN'T FIND THEM...
SEE WHAT YOU CAN DO.
YES, SIR.
TUCKER: HOW FAR AWAY ARE
THOSE ANDORIAN SHIPS?
TRAVIS: 3 HOURS
AT THEIR PRESENT SPEED.
ALIEN: THAT SHUTTLE
WAS TO BE LEFT ALONE.
I GAVE SPECIFIC ORDERS.
TARAH: AND THEY WERE FOLLOWED.
ALIEN: THEN WHO
FIRED THOSE SHOTS?
THE VULCANS, I SUPPOSE, TRYING
TO KILL THEIR OWN AMBASSADOR.
IS THAT SO UNLIKELY?
SOME OF MY MEN SAW WEAPONS FIRE
COMING FROM THEIR POSITIONS.
IT'S VULCAN SUBTERFUGE.
I'M SURE OF IT.
WHAT BETTER WAY FOR THEM
TO JUSTIFY AN INVASION
THAN TO BLAME US
FOR KILLING THEIR ENVOY?
ALIEN:
THEY ARE DEVIOUS, BUT I DOUBT
EVEN THEY WOULD GO THAT FAR.
TARAH: OH, YOU ACT AS IF THEY
HAVE SOME MORAL CODE.
THEY HAVE NO CONSCIENCE,
ONLY THEIR PRECIOUS LOGIC.
THEY'LL DO ANYTHING TO
DRIVE US OFF THIS PLANET.
WE SHOULD NEVER HAVE
AGREED TO NEGOTIATE.
ALIEN:
YOU'RE NOT HAPPY WITH THE WAY
I'VE HANDLED THIS SITUATION?
TARAH: OF COURSE I AM, SIR.
ALIEN: THE SECTOR-TWO
REPORT, SIR.
PUT OUR POSITIONS ON ALERT.
I WANT SOVAL AND THE PINK-SKIN
BROUGHT TO ME -- ALIVE.
IF THEY'RE LOOKING
FOR AN EXCUSE TO ATTACK,
WE WON'T GIVE IT TO THEM.
TARAH: I'LL SEE TO IT MYSELF.
SOVAL: PERHAPS YOU WERE FARTHER
OFF-COURSE THAN YOU THOUGHT.
ARCHER: YOU'VE BEEN HERE BEFORE.
I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'D CARE TO HELP.
SOVAL: IT'S BEEN ALMOST
A HUNDRED YEARS.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT VULCANS
HAD EXCEPTIONAL MEMORIES.
SOVAL: THIS IS
THE OLD RESIDENTIAL QUARTER.
ACCORDING TO OUR
LATEST INTELLIGENCE,
THE ANDORIANS CONTROL
THE SETTLEMENT WEST OF HERE.
ARCHER: IF WE KEEP MOVING
THIS WAY, WE SHOULD BE --
[ WEAPONS FIRE ]
DOWN!
SOVAL: NOT QUITE THE WARM
WELCOME YOU EXPECTED, CAPTAIN?
THEY'RE NOT SHOOTING AT US.
T'POL: THE VULCAN UNITS MUST
BE ADVANCING THEIR POSITIONS.
SOVAL: WE SHOULD TRY TO MAKE
CONTACT WITH THEM.
ARCHER:
I DON'T RECOMMEND STICKING
YOUR NECK OUT RIGHT NOW.
SOVAL: WHAT DO YOU RECOMMEND?
WANDERING THROUGH THESE RUINS
UNTIL WE FIND
AN ANDORIAN SOLDIER
AND TRUST HE'S BEEN INFORMED
NOT TO SHOOT US ON SIGHT?
I'LL TAKE A LOOK.
STAY HERE.
CAPTAIN.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
NO OFFENSE, BUT MY EARS ARE LESS
LIKELY TO DRAW FIRE THAN YOURS.
WHAT IS THEIR FIXATION
WITH OUR EARS?
I BELIEVE THEY'RE ENVIOUS.
DO YOU REALIZE YOU'VE PICKED UP
A SLIGHT HUMAN ACCENT?
YOU WERE ONE OF THE MOST
PROMISING MEMBERS
OF MY STAFF, T'POL.
IF YOU'D STAYED
IN SAN FRANCISCO,
YOU'D BE THE ASSISTANT COUNSEL
BY NOW.
YOU MIGHT EVEN HAVE A DIPLOMATIC
POSTING OF YOUR OWN.
T'POL: I'M AWARE OF THAT.
THEN WHY HAVE YOU
REMAINED ON ENTERPRISE?
T'POL: WE BELIEVED
THEY NEEDED OUR HELP
WHEN THEY FIRST
DEVELOPED WARP DRIVE.
THAT HASN'T CHANGED.
SOVAL: CAPTAIN ARCHER'S RECORD
IS EVIDENCE OF THAT,
BUT THERE ARE OTHERS
WHO CAN ASSIST THEM.
T'POL: I FIND
THE WORK GRATIFYING.
GRATIFICATION IS
AN EMOTIONAL INDULGENCE.
YOU DISAGREED
WITH OUR RECOMMENDATION
THAT ARCHER'S MISSION
BE CANCELED
AFTER THE TRAGEDY
AT PARAAGAN II -- WHY?
I WAS ONBOARD ENTERPRISE
AT THE TIME.
I FELT MY OPINION
WOULD BE WELCOMED.
YOU BELIEVED YOU KNEW BETTER
THAN THE HIGH COMMAND?
THAT SOUNDS A GREAT DEAL
LIKE ANOTHER EMOTION --
ARROGANCE.
PERHAPS IT'S TIME FOR YOU TO
CONSIDER ANOTHER ASSIGNMENT.
T'POL: JUST BECAUSE CAPTAIN
ARCHER HAS EARNED MY RESPECT
DOESN'T MEAN I'VE BEEN
CONTAMINATED BY HIS EMOTIONS.
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACH ]
DID YOU MAKE CONTACT?
ARCHER: NO, BUT
THEY'RE PULLING BACK.
LET'S KEEP MOVING.
EMPTY.
ALIEN: THEY'RE PROBABLY TRYING
TO REACH THE VULCANS.
TARAH:
NO. THE PINK-SKIN WILL WANT
TO KEEP HIS PART OF THE BARGAIN.
THEY'LL BE LOOKING FOR SHRAN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
COMMANDER.
TUCKER: YOU HAVE SOMETHING?
HOSHI: I CAN'T BE SURE.
YOU SEE
THIS E.M. DIFFERENTIAL HERE?
TUCKER: THAT'S THE CAPTAIN?
HOSHI: IT'S DEFINITELY
A BIO-SIGN.
I'M 90% SURE IT'S HUMAN.
TUCKER: AT LEAST
WE KNOW HE'S ALIVE.
WHERE IS HE?
HOSHI: I NEED ANOTHER HOUR.
TUCKER: WHAT'S THE STATUS
ON THOSE ANDORIAN SHIPS?
TRAVIS: THEY JUST
DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
THEY'LL BE HERE IN 13 MINUTES.
REED: I THINK THE VULCANS
SEE THEM, TOO.
THEY'RE BREAKING ORBIT,
PROBABLY GIVING THEMSELVES
ROOM TO MANEUVER.
TUCKER: PUT THE SHIP
ON TACTICAL ALERT.
GET DOWN!
GO.
UGH!
[ GROANING ]
ARCHER: OVER THERE!
T'POL: THOSE ARE
ANDORIAN WEAPONS.
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
HOW IS HE?
T'POL:
IT ISN'T LIFE-THREATENING,
BUT HE NEEDS MEDICAL ATTENTION.
WE BROUGHT THE VULCAN AMBASSADOR
TO MEET WITH COMMANDER SHRAN!
LOOKS LIKE TWO OF THEM --
ONE ON TOP OF THAT STRUCTURE...
...AND THE OTHER ON THE GROUND.
IF I CAN WORK MY WAY AROUND,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO COME
UP FROM BEHIND THEM.
SOVAL: WHAT DO YOU EXPECT ME
TO DO WITH THIS?
ARCHER: MAKE SURE
THEY DON'T SEE ME.
SOVAL: I HAVEN'T FIRED
A WEAPON IN 50 YEARS.
ARCHER:
YOU DON'T HAVE TO HIT ANYTHING.
JUST KEEP THEM OCCUPIED...
...REALLY OCCUPIED, OR I'M
NOT GONNA GET VERY FAR.
ARCHER: HEY.
TUCKER: RANGE.
TRAVIS: 50,000 KILOMETERS.
THEY'RE STILL HEADING
RIGHT FOR THE VULCAN SHIPS.
REED: THE VULCANS
ARE CHARGING WEAPONS.
THE ANDORIANS AS WELL.
TUCKER: TRAVIS,
LAY IN A NEW COURSE.
I WANT YOU TO PUT US
RIGHT BETWEEN THEM.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
REED: IF YOU DON'T
MIND ME ASKING,
WHAT DO YOU HAVE IN MIND?
[ WEAPONS FIRE ]
ARCHER: DROP YOUR WEAPON.
I'VE NEVER FIRED
ONE OF THESE BEFORE.
I'M NOT SURE
IF IT'S SET ON STUN.
T'POL, CEASE FIRE!
IT DOESN'T HAVE
A STUN SETTING.
ARCHER: YOU FIRED ON MY SHUTTLE.
YOU'RE TRYING TO KILL SOVAL,
UNDERMINE EVERYTHING THAT SHRAN
IS TRYING TO DO HERE -- WHY?
DO YOU WANT A WAR
WITH THE VULCANS?
ALL WE WANT IS A CHANCE
TO FIGHT FOR WHAT'S OURS
BEFORE COWARDS LIKE SHRAN
NEGOTIATE IT AWAY.
YOU CAN TAKE THAT UP WITH HIM.
LET'S GO.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED
BY THE VULCANS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
AND THE ANDORIANS.
PUT THEM BOTH ON.
THIS IS COMMANDER TUCKER.
CAPTAIN TELEV
OF THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
MUROC: COMMANDER,
I STRONGLY RECOMMEND
YOU WITHDRAW
TO A SAFE DISTANCE.
TELEV: I AGREE.
WE WOULDN'T WANT
YOUR VESSEL TO BE DAMAGED
BY DEBRIS
FROM THE VULCAN SHIPS.
MUROC: WE WILL NOT ALLOW
THE ANDORIANS
TO LAND ADDITIONAL TROOPS
ON PAAN MOKAR.
TELEV: IT'S CALLED WEYTAHN,
AND OUR PERSONNEL THERE
HAVE BEEN ATTACKED.
WE'LL PROVIDE
WHATEVER SUPPORT THEY NEED.
MUROC:
ANY VESSEL ATTEMPTING TO ENTER
ORBIT WILL BE FIRED UPON.
THAT INCLUDES YOURS,
SUBCOMMANDER.
TELEV: WE APPRECIATE
YOUR SUPPORT, COMMANDER TUCKER.
DON'T.
I'LL OPEN FIRE ON ANY SHIP
THAT MAKES AN AGGRESSIVE MOVE.
PHASE CANNONS?
LOCKED AND READY.
MUROC: THIS IS NOT
A STARFLEET MATTER.
AS LONG AS MY CAPTAIN IS STUCK
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOUR WAR ZONE,
IT IS.
MUROC: THE ANDORIANS
HAVE MADE IT IMPOSSIBLE
FOR US TO RECOVER
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
BY NOW, HE'S MOST LIKELY
A CASUALTY.
DON'T COUNT HIM OUT SO FAST.
WE'VE MANAGED TO ISOLATE
HIS BIO-SIGNATURE.
NOW...
WHY DON'T YOU BOTH GIVE HIM
AND AMBASSADOR SOVAL
A CHANCE TO DO THEIR JOBS
BEFORE WE START A WAR UP HERE?
TARAH: HE WAS READY TO KILL ME.
YOU SAW FOR YOURSELF.
APPARENTLY, THESE PINK-SKINS
AREN'T AS HONORABLE
AS YOU THOUGHT.
ARCHER: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I SUPPOSE I SHOT THE AMBASSADOR
TO MAKE MY STORY
MORE CONVINCING.
ALIEN: WHY WOULD MY LIEUTENANT,
A LOYAL MEMBER
OF THE IMPERIAL GUARD,
LIE TO ME?
SOVAL: COMMANDER,
IT SEEMS YOU'RE WILLING
TO RESOLVE THIS SITUATION
THROUGH PEACEFUL MEANS.
DO ALL YOUR OFFICERS
FEEL THE SAME?
T'POL: HAVE YOU CONSIDERED
THERE MIGHT BE ANDORIANS WHO
WOULD WANT A WAR WITH VULCAN?
HOW LONG HAVE I SERVED WITH YOU,
FOLLOWED YOUR ORDERS WHEN
IT COULD HAVE MEANT MY LIFE?
ARCHER: SHE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE
WHO RISKED THEIR LIFE.
I SAID I'D BRING SOVAL
TO MEET YOU,
AND WE DAMN NEAR GOT KILLED
GETTING HIM HERE.
I CAME BECAUSE YOU ASKED ME,
BECAUSE YOU THOUGHT
I COULD BE TRUSTED.
CHECK SOVAL'S WOUND.
CHECK OUR SHUTTLE.
YOU'LL FIND
ANDORIAN WEAPONS SIGNATURES.
ALIEN: IS THIS TRUE?
ANSWER ME!
TARAH: WHAT DID YOU
EXPECT ME TO DO?
ALIEN: FOLLOW MY ORDERS!
TARAH: ORDERS TO DO NOTHING
WHILE YOU BETRAY US?
IT'S NOT TOO LATE
TO REDEEM YOURSELF,
TO MAKE A STAND.
ALIEN: I INTEND TO.
TAKE HER.
TARAH: THERE ARE OTHERS
WHO FEEL THIS WAY.
YOU'LL SEE.
ALIEN:
SEE TO THE AMBASSADOR'S WOUNDS.
WE HAVE A LOT TO DISCUSS.
THE VULCAN SHIPS
ARE BREAKING FORMATION.
THEY'RE HEADING
FOR THE PLANET.
TRAVIS: THE ANDORIANS
ARE FOLLOWING, SIR.
TUCKER: ARM THE FORWARD
PHASE CANNONS.
SEE IF YOU CAN TARGET
THEIR WEAPONS.
WE'RE BEING HAILED
FROM THE SURFACE.
IT'S THE CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: HOLD OFF, MALCOLM.
PUT HIM THROUGH.
CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: NICE TO HEAR
YOUR VOICE, TRIP.
TUCKER: WHAT'S GOING ON
DOWN THERE?
ARE YOU OKAY?
ARCHER: T'POL AND I ARE FINE.
WE'RE AT THE ANDORIAN
COMMAND POST.
AMBASSADOR SOVAL'S BEEN INJURED,
BUT SHRAN'S MEDICS
ARE TREATING HIM.
DID YOU SAY SHRAN'S MEDICS?
ARCHER: HE'S JUST
BEING A GOOD HOST.
THE ANDORIANS ARE ALLOWING
THE VULCAN SHIPS
TO MOVE IN AND PICK UP
THEIR PEOPLE.
GLAD YOU LET US KNOW.
ARCHER: DID YOU RUN INTO
ANY PROBLEMS UP THERE?
NOTHING WE COULDN'T HANDLE.
I'LL FILL YOU IN LATER.
ARCHER: WE HAD
A PRETTY ROUGH LANDING.
WE'LL NEED A RIDE
BACK TO THE SHIP.
I'LL SEND TRAVIS DOWN
IN SHUTTLEPOD 2.
ARCHER: ACKNOWLEDGED.
ARCHER OUT.
TUCKER:
PUT US BACK IN ORBIT, TRAVIS,
AND CANCEL THE TACTICAL ALERT.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
AMBASSADOR SOVAL HAS BEGUN
TALKS WITH THE ANDORIANS.
THEY'VE BEEN DIFFICULT,
BUT PRODUCTIVE.
THE IMPERIAL COUNCIL
WILL NOT BE SATISFIED
UNTIL VULCAN RECOGNIZES
OUR CLAIM TO WEYTAHN.
ARCHER: I BELIEVE SOMEONE
ONCE DEFINED A COMPROMISE
AS A SOLUTION THAT NEITHER SIDE
IS HAPPY WITH.
ALIEN: IN THAT CASE, THESE TALKS
HAVE BEEN EXTREMELY SUCCESSFUL.
SOVAL:
I CONSIDER ANY NEGOTIATION
THAT AVERTS WAR TO BE A SUCCESS.
ALIEN: JOIN ME...IN A DRINK...
TO CELEBRATE...
OUR MUTUAL DISSATISFACTION.
SOVAL: VULCANS DON'T DRINK.
BUT THIS OCCASION
MERITS AN EXCEPTION.
TO THE CEASE-FIRE.
IT WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN POSSIBLE
WITHOUT THE HELP
OF OUR HUMAN FRIENDS.
SOVAL: AND TO THE SUCCESSFUL
CONTINUATION OF THESE TALKS
ON ANDORIA.
I TRUST THERE'LL BE MORE
ACCOMPLISHED THAN JUST TALK.
T'POL: WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
I'LL ESCORT AMBASSADOR SOVAL
TO THE AIRLOCK.
OF COURSE.
SOVAL: CAPTAIN.
YOUR PRESENCE HERE
HAS NOT BEEN...
OVERLY MEDDLESOME.
ALIEN: I THINK HE LIKES YOU,
PINK-SKIN.
ARCHER: I WOULDN'T GO THAT FAR.