ARCHER: BIO-SIGNS?
T'POL: NONE THAT I CAN DETECT.
BUT ITS HULL SEEMS TO BE
SCATTERING OUR SENSORS.
ARCHER: ANY IDEA WHAT HAPPENED?
REED: I'M NOT READING
ANY WEAPONS SIGNATURES.
POSSIBLY SOME SORT OF ACCIDENT.
ARCHER: BRING IT INTO
LAUNCH BAY 2.
THERE'S NO WINDOWS.
I'M NOT SURE WHETHER
THIS END'S THE BOW OR THE STERN.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
THIS MIGHT BE A HATCH.
REED: IF IT IS,
IT'S BEEN FUSED SHUT.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION, SIR.
[ COUGHING ]
[ SCANNER BEEPING ]
HE'S HUMAN.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
PHLOX: THIS WAS A HUMAN MALE.
A MICROCELLULAR SCAN SHOULD TELL
US HIS AGE AT THE TIME OF DEATH.
APPARENTLY, YOU'RE NOT
THE FIRST HUMANS OUT THIS FAR.
ARCHER: WHOEVER THIS IS, HE'S
REWRITTEN OUR HISTORY BOOKS.
CAN YOU GET A DNA SAMPLE?
PHLOX: THE TISSUE DAMAGE
IS EXTENSIVE,
BUT I SHOULD BE ABLE TO ISOLATE
A FEW FRAGMENTS.
ARCHER: IF HE'S
A MEMBER OF STARFLEET,
HIS GENETIC PROFILE
IS PROBABLY IN OUR DATABASE.
RUN A COMPARISON
AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
ABSOLUTELY.
THERE AREN'T ANY SHIPS
OR INHABITED SYSTEMS
FOR SEVERAL LIGHT-YEARS.
I WONDER...
IF THIS COULD BE
ZEFRAM COCHRANE.
THEY SAY HE WAS PILOTING
A ONE-MAN VESSEL
WHEN HE DISAPPEARED.
T'POL: HOW COULD HE
HAVE TRAVELED THIS FAR?
ARCHER: THERE WERE A LOT OF
RUMORS AFTER HE WAS LOST.
ONE OF THEM SAID HE WAS TESTING
SOME KIND
OF EXPERIMENTAL WARP SHIP.
ANY MARKINGS ON THE HULL
OR CONTROL PANELS?
T'POL: WE HAVEN'T FOUND ANY.
REED: THE HULL SEEMS
TO ABSORB E.M. RADIATION.
WITHOUT ALL THIS DAMAGE,
IT NEVER WOULD HAVE SHOWN UP
ON OUR SENSORS.
TUCKER: SOME KIND
OF STEALTH SHIP.
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK, TRAVIS?
COULD THIS PILOT HAVE
BEEN A CARGO HAULER?
TRAVIS:
WE'RE MORE THAN 30 LIGHT-YEARS
FROM THE NEAREST TRADE ROUTE.
I DON'T SEE HOW HE COULD
HAVE MADE IT OUT THIS FAR.
MAYBE HE GOT A RIDE
FROM SOMEONE.
TUCKER: THAT'S GOT TO BE A
WORLD RECORD FOR HITCHHIKING.
I STILL CAN'T FIND
ANY PLASMA EXHAUST PORTS.
NOT EVEN A THRUSTER QUAD.
TRAVIS: THERE'S NOTHING HERE
THAT LOOKS LIKE A POWER SOURCE.
HOW DID THIS THING MAKE IT INTO
DEEP SPACE WITHOUT AN ENGINE?
REED: COULD BE AN ESCAPE POD.
EVEN AN ESCAPE POD WOULD NEED
SOME KIND OF PROPULSION SYSTEM.
ANY NEW MISSION
YOU HAVEN'T TOLD US ABOUT?
FORREST: I WISH THERE WAS.
IT'S POSSIBLE THE SHIP
YOU FOUND
WAS LAUNCHED
FROM VEGA COLONY,
BUT THEY'RE A LONG WAY
BEHIND YOU.
THE EARTH CARGO AUTHORITY
MAY HAVE MORE INFORMATION.
PHLOX HAS SENT A REQUEST
TO DR. COCHRANE'S FAMILY.
THEY'RE TRANSMITTING
HIS GENETIC PROFILE.
A HUNDRED LIGHT-YEARS
FROM EARTH,
AND YOU MIGHT HAVE SOLVED
THE GREATEST MISSING-PERSON
CASE OF THE CENTURY.
IF WE HAVEN'T, WE'VE DISCOVERED
AN EVEN BIGGER MYSTERY.
[ GRUNTING ]
COMMANDER.
REGISTERS AS SOME KIND
OF BIOMATTER.
ORGANIC CIRCUITRY?
MAYBE WE SHOULD GET PHLOX
TO COME DOWN AND TAKE A LOOK.
NOT A BAD IDEA.
[ GRUNTING ]
WHAT'S THIS?
REED: THERE WE GO.
[ GRUNTS ]
TUCKER: MALCOLM?
REED: I SEE IT.
TUCKER: GOOD.
MEANS I'M NOT HALLUCINATING.
HOW COULD A SHIP BE BIGGER ON
THE INSIDE THAN THE OUTSIDE?
IT COULD BE A HOLOGRAM.
TUCKER: HAND ME
THAT HYPERSPANNER.
[ CLANG ]
REED: YOU'RE NOT
GOING DOWN THERE.
GOT TO GET MY SPANNER BACK.
WE SHOULD CALL THE BRIDGE FIRST,
LET THEM KNOW --
SAY AGAIN, MALCOLM?
REED: THIS GIVES SPACE
EXPLORATION A WHOLE NEW MEANING.
TUCKER: I'VE READ A FEW PAPERS
ON SPATIAL GEOMETRY,
BUT I NEVER HEARD A THEORY
THAT WOULD EXPLAIN THIS.
THE CAPTAIN WILL NEVER
BELIEVE US.
HE'S GONNA HAVE
TO SEE THIS FOR HIMSELF.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
A WARP REACTOR?
REED: YOU'RE THE ENGINEER.
TUCKER: LOOKS LIKE A BREACH
OR AN OVERLOAD
OF SOME KIND.
I'M PICKING UP
AN ENERGY SIGNATURE.
IT'S VERY FAINT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TRAVIS: SIR, A VESSEL'S
DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
THEY'RE ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
T'POL: IT'S SULIBAN.
ARCHER: LET'S SEE IT.
T'POL: MINIMAL WEAPONS.
I DON'T BELIEVE
IT'S A COMBAT SHIP.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
YOU HAVE SOMETHING
THAT BELONGS TO US.
I DON'T BELIEVE I'VE HAD
THE PLEASURE --
WE HAVE A SALVAGE CLAIM ON
THE VESSEL IN YOUR LAUNCH BAY.
ONE OF OUR CELL SHIPS
DISCOVERED IT 3 DAYS AGO.
WE WERE SENT TO RETRIEVE IT.
THAT SHIP'S AN EARTH VESSEL.
THE PILOT'S HUMAN.
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN THE CORPSE.
DECOMPRESS YOUR LAUNCH BAY
AND RELEASE THE VESSEL.
I'M CURIOUS.
WHAT'S YOUR INTEREST
IN THAT SHIP?
THERE'S NOT MUCH LEFT.
THE VESSEL. NOW.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO CONTACT YOUR SUPERIORS.
ASK FOR A MAN NAMED SILIK.
HE'LL TELL YOU I DON'T RESPOND
WELL TO THREATS.
[ GRUNTING ]
TUCKER: THIS COULD BE
A RELEASE PIN.
LET'S GET IT TO ENGINEERING.
[ EXPLOSION ]
UGH!
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
T'POL: FORWARD PLATING
IS HOLDING.
ARCHER: BRING US ABOUT, TRAVIS.
POWER THE PHASE CANNONS.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN DO
ABOUT THEIR WEAPONS.
TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE.
THE COM'S DOWN.
UGH!
COMMANDER!
SOMEONE'S TRYING
TO OPEN LAUNCH BAY 2.
ARCHER: LOCK THEM OUT!
HOSHI: I CAN'T.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO TRIP.
SEND A SECURITY TEAM DOWN THERE.
RETURN FIRE.
THEIR WEAPONS
HAVE BEEN DISABLED.
ARCHER: TARGET THEIR ENGINES,
AND BRING THE GRAPPLER ONLINE.
T'POL: SIR.
ARCHER: THEY WANTED
THAT SHIP PRETTY BADLY.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW WHY.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE MOVING OFF.
ARCHER: STAY WITH THEM.
I'VE LOST THEM, SIR.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE CONTACTED
THE VULCAN SHIP TAL'KIR.
THEY'VE AGREED TO MEET US
IN 3 DAYS
TO TAKE THE CRAFT
BACK TO EARTH.
HOPEFULLY, WE WON'T HAVE
ANOTHER VISIT FROM THE SULIBAN
BEFORE WE REACH
THE RENDEZVOUS POINT.
TUCKER: IT WAS
HEAVILY SHIELDED.
WHATEVER THIS THING IS,
IT MUST BE PRETTY IMPORTANT.
ARCHER: WHAT'S YOUR GUESS?
TUCKER: IT MIGHT BE
THE BLACK BOX.
T'POL:
IT COULD TELL US WHAT HAPPENED,
MAYBE EVEN WHO BUILT THE VESSEL.
TUCKER: THAT'S ASSUMING
WE CAN GET IT WORKING.
IT SEEMS TO USE THE SAME
ORGANIC CIRCUITRY
AS THE REST OF THE SHIP.
CAPTAIN, I GOT TO TAKE YOU
DOWN INTO THAT CHAMBER.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BELIEVE YOUR EYES.
ARCHER: BIGGER ON THE INSIDE?
TUCKER: OH.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
PHLOX: SICK BAY
TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: ARCHER.
PHLOX: I NEED TO
SEE YOU IMMEDIATELY.
PHLOX: I MANAGED TO FIND
ONLY A FEW UNDAMAGED CELLS,
BUT THEY WERE ENOUGH TO COMPLETE
A GENETIC ANALYSIS.
ARCHER: ANY MATCH
IN THE STARFLEET DATABASE?
PHLOX: NO, BUT I DID DISCOVER
THAT OUR GUEST IS
NO ORDINARY HUMAN.
I FOUND A --
AN UNUSUAL DEVIATION
IN THIS NUCLEOTIDE SEQUENCE.
AT FIRST I THOUGHT I WAS LOOKING
AT SOME KIND OF MUTATION,
BUT THERE WAS SOMETHING FAMILIAR
ABOUT THE CHROMOSOME STRUCTURE,
SO I WIDENED MY SEARCH
TO INCLUDE
THE INTERSPECIES DATABASE.
THIS NUCLEOTIDE SEQUENCE...
IS VULCAN.
HOW DID A HUMAN END UP
WITH VULCAN DNA?
THE LIKELIEST EXPLANATION
IS THAT HE HAD AT LEAST
ONE VULCAN ANCESTOR --
FURTHER BACK THAN
A GREAT-GRANDPARENT.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
WE HAVEN'T KNOWN THE VULCANS
LONG ENOUGH.
I ALSO FOUND GENETIC MATERIAL
BELONGING
TO SEVERAL OTHER SPECIES.
THIS SEQUENCE IS TERRELLIAN.
THERE'S ANOTHER
I CAN'T IDENTIFY.
I BELIEVE THIS INDIVIDUAL
IS THE RESULT
OF SEVERAL GENERATIONS
OF INTERSPECIES BREEDING.
ARCHER: THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
T'POL.
T'POL: A DATABASE
FROM THE FUTURE?
ARCHER:
OUR TIME-TRAVELING FRIEND
DANIELS LEFT IT IN HIS QUARTERS.
T'POL: I'M NOT CERTAIN DANIELS
WOULD APPROVE OF THIS.
ARCHER: WE'LL KEEP IT
TO OURSELVES.
T'POL: A VULCAN CRUISER.
I DON'T RECOGNIZE
THE CONFIGURATION.
ARCHER: THAT'S BECAUSE
IT HASN'T BEEN BUILT YET.
FEW VULCANS HAVE EVER CHOSEN
TO MATE WITH ANOTHER SPECIES.
WORRIED ABOUT CONTAMINATING YOUR
GENOME WITH A LITTLE HUMAN DNA?
THERE ARE SIGNIFICANT BIOLOGICAL
DIFFERENCES BETWEEN THE SPECIES.
IT'S UNLIKELY
WE COULD REPRODUCE.
HUMANS AND VULCANS.
ARCHER: MM.
ARCHER: THAT COULD BE IT.
T'POL: THE DORSAL SECTION
IS THE WRONG SHAPE.
ARCHER: IF A HUMAN AND A VULCAN
DID HAVE A CHILD,
I WONDER IF HE'D HAVE
POINTED EARS.
THERE.
I THINK THAT'S IT.
ARCHER: LOOK AT
THE COMMISSION DATE.
THAT'S ALMOST 900 YEARS
FROM NOW.
DANIELS TALKED ABOUT HISTORIANS
FROM THE FUTURE,
PEOPLE WHO TRAVELED BACK
TO STUDY THE PAST.
THAT COULD BE WHAT
THIS PILOT WAS DOING.
THIS SAYS IT'S POWERED BY
A TEMPORAL DISPLACEMENT DRIVE.
ARCHER: IF THE SULIBAN
GET THEIR HANDS ON THIS,
THEY'LL TAKE IT APART,
MAYBE LEARN
HOW THE ENGINE WORKS.
IT COULD CHANGE THE COURSE
OF THE TEMPORAL COLD WAR.
ASSUMING THE VESSEL
IS FROM THE FUTURE,
WHY HAVEN'T THEY RETRIEVED IT?
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
TRAVIS:
SIR, ANOTHER ALIEN VESSEL'S
APPROACHING AT HIGH WARP.
SULIBAN?
TRAVIS: NO, SIR.
WE CAN'T IDENTIFY THEM.
TRAVIS: 20,000
KILOMETERS AND CLOSING.
ARCHER: T'POL?
T'POL: THE VESSEL'S THOLIAN.
THEY'RE EXTREMELY XENOPHOBIC.
THE HIGH COMMAND'S HAD
LIMITED CONTACT WITH THEM.
CAPTAIN, IT'S UNUSUAL
FOR THOLIANS TO TRAVEL
THIS FAR FROM THEIR SYSTEM.
REED: I'M GETTING
UNUSUAL THERMAL READINGS.
IT'S AWFULLY WARM
INSIDE THAT SHIP --
MORE THAN 200 DEGREES.
THEY'RE BELIEVE TO BE
A NONHUMANOID SPECIES.
ARCHER: OPEN A CHANNEL.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER
OF THE STARSHIP --
[ SQUEALING, GRUNTING ]
ALIEN: JONATHAN ARCHER.
PLEASE ESTABLISH COMMUNICATION.
IS THERE SOMETHING
WE CAN DO FOR YOU?
[ SQUEALS, GRUNTS ]
WE WERE SENT
TO RETRIEVE THE VESSEL.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW HOW YOU HEARD
ABOUT THAT SHIP.
IT IS DANGEROUS TO YOU.
TEMPORAL RADIATION.
ARCHER: THANKS FOR THE WARNING.
BUT WE CAN'T GIVE IT TO YOU.
[ SQUEALS ]
[ THUMP ]
THEY'VE LOCKED ON TO US
WITH A TRACTOR BEAM.
TRAVIS: WE'RE LOSING SPEED.
ARCHER: HULL PLATING.
ARM THE AFT TORPEDOES.
REED: THAT BEAM'S INTERFERING
WITH OUR TARGETING SCANNERS.
ARCHER:
RELEASE US, OR I'LL DESTROY
THE SHIP IN OUR LAUNCH BAY.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
[ SQUEALS, GRUNTS ]
WHAT DID HE SAY?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT I DON'T THINK HE
WAS PAYING YOU A COMPLIMENT.
[ SIGHS ]
I WONDER IF THERE'S ANYONE ELSE
WHO THINKS THEY HAVE
A CLAIM ON THAT SHIP.
PHLOX: MAY I JOIN YOU?
T'POL: PLEASE.
PHLOX: I FOUND
ANOTHER NUCLEOTIDE SEQUENCE
IN THE PILOT'S GENOME.
IT APPEARS TO BE RIGELIAN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THAT CORPSE IS
FULL OF SURPRISES.
MM-MMM.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
HOW LATE IT WAS
UNTIL MY STOMACH REMINDED ME
IT WAS TIME TO EAT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
AH, YOU SEEM TO BE ENGROSSED
IN YOUR WORK AS WELL.
THE CAPTAIN ASKED ME
TO PERFORM
A METALLURGICAL ANALYSIS
OF THE VESSEL'S HULL.
ANYTHING NOTEWORTHY?
I HAVE DISCOVERED
SEVERAL UNUSUAL ALLOYS.
ONE OF THEM IS
IN A SEMI-FLUIDIC STATE.
HMM. MORE MYSTERIES.
TO SAY THE LEAST.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I UNDERSTAND
CAPTAIN ARCHER BELIEVES
THAT THE VESSEL TRAVELED HERE
FROM THE FUTURE.
THAT'S HIS THEORY.
GENETIC ANOMALIES,
UNEXPLAINABLE ALLOYS --
THE EVIDENCE SEEMS
TO BE MOUNTING.
PERHAPS.
PHLOX: AH, THE VULCAN
SCIENCE DIRECTORATE.
THEY'VE ALWAYS BEEN
RATHER RELUCTANT
TO EMBRACE UNORTHODOX IDEAS.
AFTER THEY REVIEW OUR FINDINGS,
I HAVE A FEELING
THEY MIGHT RECONSIDER
THEIR OPINION OF TIME TRAVEL.
IT'S NOT AN OPINION.
IT'S SIMPLE LOGIC.
THERE WAS A TIME
WHEN DENOBULANS BELIEVED
THEY WERE THE ONLY INTELLIGENT
SPECIES IN THE GALAXY.
NEEDLESS TO SAY,
IT WAS QUITE A SURPRISE
WHEN THE B'SAARI MADE
FIRST CONTACT.
MANY REFUSED TO ACCEPT
THE TRUTH
EVEN WITH THE EVIDENCE
STANDING RIGHT IN FRONT OF THEM.
IT TOOK SOME TIME,
AND IT WASN'T EASY,
BUT EVENTUALLY WE WERE FORCED
TO REEVALUATE OUR BELIEFS.
T'POL:
ARE YOU SAYING YOU BELIEVE
TIME TRAVEL IS POSSIBLE?
SURPRISES, SUBCOMMANDER --
I BELIEVE
IN EMBRACING SURPRISES.
I PREFER TO EMBRACE LOGIC.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, DOCTOR.
GOOD NIGHT.
TUCKER: ALL RIGHT, LET'S START
REINITIALIZING THE POWER GRID.
REED: ASSUMING THAT IS
THE POWER GRID.
IT BOGGLES THE MIND
IF YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
TUCKER: WHAT DOES?
REED: THAT SHIP COULD BE
FROM THE 31st CENTURY.
WHEN I WAS YOUNG,
I ALWAYS WANTED TO BUILD
A TIME MACHINE,
SEE THE FUTURE.
TUCKER: YOU'RE PROBABLY
THE KIND OF PERSON
THAT JUMPS TO THE END OF A BOOK
BEFORE YOU READ IT.
REED: DON'T TELL ME
YOU'VE NEVER WONDERED
WHAT IT WOULD BE LIKE --
HOW OUR MISSION
WILL TURN OUT.
TUCKER: WELL, WONDERING ABOUT
THE FUTURE AND KNOWING IT
ARE TWO DIFFERENT THINGS.
REED: IF DANIELS CAME HERE
AND OFFERED YOU A CHANCE
TO GO TO THE 31st CENTURY,
YOU WOULDN'T TAKE IT?
TUCKER: SOME THINGS ARE
BETTER LEFT A MYSTERY.
REED: AND YOU CALL YOURSELF
AN EXPLORER.
TUCKER: WHERE'S THE FUN
IN EXPLORING
IF YOU KNOW
HOW IT ALL TURNS OUT?
HAND ME THAT MICRO-CALIPER.
TUCKER: SUPPOSE YOU COULD LOOK
INTO SOME FUTURE BOOK
AND FIND OUT THE NAME
OF THE WOMAN
YOU'RE GONNA MARRY.
WOULD YOU WANT TO KNOW IT?
REED: ABSOLUTELY.
THINK OF ALL THE AWKWARD
FIRST DATES I COULD AVOID.
[ REED CHUCKLES ]
TUCKER: FINE.
SO, ONE DAY YOU MEET JANE DOE.
YOU GO OUT A FEW TIMES,
AND YOU POP THE QUESTION.
SHE SAYS "I DO," AND THE TWO
OF YOU LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER.
REED: SOUNDS PERFECT.
TUCKER: NOW, DID YOU
MARRY HER FOR LOVE
OR BECAUSE SOME BOOK
TOLD YOU TO?
WELL, IF WE'RE
HAPPILY EVER AFTER,
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
[ TUCKER SIGHS ]
AH. WE'VE GOT POWER.
NOW I'VE GOT TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO TAP INTO
THESE ORGANIC CIRCUITS.
THEY'RE SIMILAR TO THE ONES
IN THE COCKPIT.
HMM.
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SALVAGE SOME OF THEM,
BUILD AN INTERFACE.
NOW, IF I HAD A CHANCE
TO SEE THE PAST, I'D JUMP AT IT.
I ALWAYS WANTED TO MEET
A STEGOSAURUS.
REED: HE'D PROBABLY MAKE
A QUICK MEAL OF YOU.
TUCKER: THE STEGOSAURUS
WAS AN HERBIVORE.
REED: IF I COULD
TRAVEL BACK IN TIME,
I KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT YEAR I'D PICK.
1588.
TUCKER: WHAT HAPPENED IN 1588?
REED: ENGLAND DEFEATED
THE SPANISH ARMADA.
TUCKER:
I'M SURE SOMEONE NAMED REED
HAD A LOT TO DO WITH THAT.
NOW, IF I HAD A CHANCE
TO SEE THE PAST, I'D JUMP AT IT.
I ALWAYS WANTED TO MEET
A STEGOSAURUS.
REED: HE'D PROBABLY MAKE
A QUICK MEAL OF YOU.
TUCKER: THE STEGOSAURUS
WAS AN HERBIVORE.
IT SEEMS LIKE WE WERE
JUST IN HERE.
IF I COULD TRAVEL BACK,
I KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT YEAR I'D PICK.
TUCKER: 1588?
REED: 1588.
TUCKER: HOW'D I KNOW
YOU WERE GONNA SAY THAT?
REED: I THINK WE'RE SPENDING
FAR TOO MUCH TIME TOGETHER.
[ TUCKER CHUCKLES ]
NOW, IF I HAD A CHANCE
TO SEE THE PAST, I'D JUMP AT IT.
REED: "I ALWAYS WANTED
TO MEET A STEGOSAURUS."
TUCKER: "HE'D PROBABLY MAKE
A QUICK MEAL OF YOU."
"THE STEGOSAURUS
WAS A HERBIVORE."
TUCKER: IT WAS
THE WEIRDEST THING.
WHEN WE WERE STANDING
NEXT TO THE SHIP,
IT FELT LIKE WE WERE HAVING
THE SAME CONVERSATION
OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
PHLOX:
HMM. I CAN'T FIND ANYTHING
WRONG WITH EITHER OF YOU.
REED: WE DIDN'T IMAGINE
WHAT HAPPENED.
T'POL: CAPTAIN, THE CRAFT
IS EMITTING SOME TYPE
OF HIGH-ENERGY PARTICLES.
ARCHER: THIS MAY BE
THE TEMPORAL RADIATION
THE THOLIANS WARNED US ABOUT.
REED: WE SPENT A FAIR AMOUNT
OF TIME AROUND THAT SHIP.
PHLOX: THE PARTICLE DENSITY
IS QUITE LOW.
IT'S UNLIKELY TO HAVE
ANY LASTING EFFECTS.
TUCKER: HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
WHAT HAPPENED?
THE RADIATION
COULD HAVE AFFECTED
YOUR PERCEPTION OF TIME.
OR MAYBE THEY REALLY WERE
RELIVING THE SAME MOMENT.
SEAL OFF LAUNCH BAY 2
AND EVACUATE
THE SURROUNDING SECTIONS.
I DON'T WANT
TO TAKE ANY CHANCES.
HOW ARE YOU COMING
WITH THE BLACK BOX?
TUCKER: THE POWER'S ONLINE, BUT
WE STILL CAN'T ACCESS THE DATA.
LET ME KNOW AS SOON AS YOU FIND
ANYTHING. DISMISSED.
T'POL: CAN I SPEAK WITH YOU?
T'POL: THE RADIATION COULD
SPREAD TO OTHER SECTIONS,
AFFECT MORE SYSTEMS.
ARCHER: WE'LL KEEP AN EYE ON IT.
THE VULCANS ARE ONLY
A FEW HOURS AWAY.
T'POL: I'M NOT CERTAIN
WE'LL SURVIVE THAT LONG.
WE'VE ATTRACTED THE ATTENTION
OF TWO HOSTILE SPECIES.
IT'S LOGICAL TO ASSUME
THEY'RE SEARCHING FOR US.
ARCHER: I'M PRETTY SURE
WE CAN STEER CLEAR OF THEM.
T'POL: PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
DESTROY THE VESSEL.
ARCHER: I'M NOT GONNA DO THAT.
I'M TIRED OF THESE FACTIONS
INTERFERING WITH OUR CENTURY.
IT'S TIME WE TOOK A MORE
ACTIVE INTEREST IN THIS WAR,
GATHERED SOME INTELLIGENCE
OURSELVES.
T'POL: ASSUMING FOR THE MOMENT
THE TEMPORAL COLD WAR EXISTS,
I BELIEVE WE SHOULDN'T
GET INVOLVED.
ARCHER: LIKE IT OR NOT,
WE'VE BEEN INVOLVED
SINCE WE LEFT SPACEDOCK.
DANIELS HINTED THAT THERE WERE
OTHER FACTIONS IN THIS CONFLICT.
MAYBE THE THOLIANS ARE
WORKING FOR ONE OF THEM.
T'POL: YOUR CURIOSITY
IS PLACING ENTERPRISE
IN UNNECESSARY DANGER.
ARCHER: THIS IS THE FIRST CHANCE
WE'VE HAD TO GET SOME ANSWERS.
I'M NOT GONNA PASS IT UP.
THE VULCANS CAN GET THAT SHIP
BACK TO EARTH IN A FEW WEEKS.
STARFLEET WILL TAKE IT
FROM THERE.
T'POL: CAPTAIN --
ARCHER: I TOLD YOU.
I'VE MADE MY DECISION.
IF THE SULIBAN RETURN,
THEY MAY BE CLOAKED.
I RECOMMEND WE GO
TO TACTICAL ALERT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
TUCKER: IT'S WHAT
WE DON'T HAVE.
THIS ISN'T A BLACK BOX.
WE THOUGHT IT WAS
A DATA-STORAGE MATRIX,
BUT AFTER WE GOT
THE POWER RUNNING,
IT STARTED GENERATING
A SUBSPACE SIGNATURE.
I THINK IT'S
A MICRO-TRANSMITTER,
SOME KIND
OF EMERGENCY BEACON.
T'POL: BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
SEVERAL SULIBAN VESSELS
ARE APPROACHING.
ARCHER: ON MY WAY.
T'POL: ACKNOWLEDGED.
T'POL: THE SHIPS WILL BE WITHIN
WEAPONS RANGE IN 20 SECONDS.
ARCHER: GO TO MAXIMUM WARP.
T'POL: THEY'RE
MATCHING OUR SPEED.
ARCHER: HOW LONG TO
THE RENDEZVOUS POINT?
T'POL: LESS THAN 3 MINUTES.
ARCHER: CONTACT THE TAL'KIR.
LET THEM KNOW
WE'RE BRINGING COMPANY.
HOSHI: NO RESPONSE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED
BY THE SULIBAN.
I SEE YOU BROUGHT
SOME FRIENDS WITH YOU.
DROP OUT OF WARP
AND PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
OR WHAT?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA RISK
ANY MORE DAMAGE TO THAT SHIP.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
TAKE A LOOK
AT YOUR LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
THERE'S A VULCAN COMBAT CRUISER
A FEW MILLION KILOMETERS
FROM HERE.
UNLESS YOU WANT TO UPSET THEM,
I SUGGEST YOU TURN AROUND.
THE VULCANS WON'T RISK
THEIR SHIP FOR AN EARTH VESSEL.
ARCHER: AFT CANNON.
RETURN FIRE.
REED: WE'RE LOSING
VENTRAL PLATING.
ARCHER: THE VULCANS?
T'POL: 600,000 KILOMETERS.
REED: DIRECT HIT
TO THE LAUNCH-BAY DOORS.
THEY'RE TRYING
TO BLAST THEM OPEN.
ARCHER: HOLD YOUR
COURSE AND SPEED.
200,000 KILOMETERS.
ARCHER: TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
ARCHER: BIO-SIGNS?
T'POL: THE CREW'S ALIVE.
THE VESSEL IS DISABLED.
THEIR COM SYSTEM'S DOWN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
TRAVIS: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: TAKE US BACK TO WARP.
ENGINES ARE DOWN.
ARCHER: WEAPONS?
REED: THEY'RE OFFLINE, TOO.
THE HULL PLATING'S
DEPOLARIZING.
THE CELL SHIPS
HAVE DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D BE GLAD
TO SEE THE SULIBAN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TRIP, WE COULD USE WARP ENGINES
RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
THE ANTIMATTER INJECTORS
ARE FUSED.
I'LL NEED A FEW HOURS
TO REPLACE THEM.
ARCHER: HOW ABOUT WEAPONS?
EVERY POWER RELAY
ON THE SHIP'S BEEN SCRAMBLED.
ARCHER:
THEN FORGET EVERYTHING ELSE.
GET THAT BEACON WORKING.
SIR?
WHOEVER BUILT THAT SHIP
MIGHT BE ABLE TO SEND HELP.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
EVEN IF YOU'RE CORRECT,
IT'S UNLIKELY HELP
WILL ARRIVE IN TIME.
ARCHER:
HOW LONG WOULD IT TAKE TO REMOVE
ONE OF THE TORPEDO WARHEADS,
ARM IT MANUALLY?
REED: 4 MINUTES --
LESS IF I HAD SOME HELP.
I RECOMMEND MOVING THE WARHEAD
AS LITTLE AS POSSIBLE
ONCE WE REMOVE IT.
ARCHER: THEN WE'LL BRING
THE TORPEDO TO THE LAUNCH BAY,
WORK ON IT THERE.
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE.
I'M GONNA HOLD YOU
TO THAT 4 MINUTES.
REED: IT WAS ONLY
AN ESTIMATE, SIR.
ARCHER: THEY DON'T MAKE
THIS EASY, DO THEY?
REED: I'M GOING TO RELEASE
THE COUPLINGS.
YOU'LL NEED TO DISCONNECT
THE POWER CONDUITS,
THE BLUE AND RED ONES FIRST.
TURN THE RELEASE
COUNTERCLOCKWISE
UNTIL YOU FEEL IT DETACH.
[ WHIRRING ]
CREWMAN: COMMANDER?
TUCKER: I NEED THAT
POWER MODULE.
CREMAN: YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, HAND ME
A MICRO-CALIPER.
T'POL: BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: THE SULIBAN HAVE LOST
MORE THAN HALF OF THEIR SHIPS.
YOU DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
ARCHER: WE'RE WORKING
AS FAST AS WE CAN.
STAND BY.
REED: SIR, IF YOU'LL HOLD IT
BY THE LOCKING BRACE.
ARCHER: I'M GONNA HOLD YOU
TO THAT 4 MINUTES.
REED: IT WAS ONLY
AN ESTIMATE, SIR.
IT'S HAPPENING AGAIN.
WE'VE HAD
THIS CONVERSATION BEFORE.
ARCHER: YOU'RE RIGHT.
HOW FAR DO YOU THINK
WE GOT LAST TIME?
REED: I'M NOT CERTAIN.
ARCHER: I THINK WE MAY HAVE
REMOVED THE WARHEAD.
REED: IF TIME'S NOT REPEATING
OUTSIDE THE LAUNCH BAY,
THE THOLIANS COULD BE CLOSE.
ARCHER: WE'D BETTER HURRY.
THE RED AND BLUE CONDUITS,
RIGHT?
[ WHIRRING ]
TRAVIS: THE CELL SHIPS --
THEY'VE BEEN DESTROYED.
T'POL: HOW MANY?
TRAVIS: ALL OF THEM.
TRAVIS: THE THOLIANS ARE
ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
HOSHI: THEY'RE HAILING US.
[ SQUEALING, GRUNTING ]
ALIEN: GIVE US THE VESSEL.
WE'RE PREPARED
TO SURRENDER IT TO YOU.
BUT OUR LAUNCH-BAY DOORS
TOOK HEAVY DAMAGE.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED MORE TIME.
I HAVE A REPAIR TEAM
WORKING ON IT,
BUT THEY ESTIMATE
IT WILL TAKE --
[ SQUEALS, GRUNTS ]
TRAVIS: TWO OF THEIR SHIPS ARE
APPROACHING THE SAUCER SECTION.
80 METERS.
40.
THEY'VE LOCKED ON
TO BOTH DOCKING PORTS.
T'POL: SEAL THE HATCHES
AND SEND SECURITY TEAMS.
ARCHER: GET TO THE CONTROL ROOM.
ARCHER: I'LL TAKE IT FROM HERE.
REED: AYE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: I'M GONNA HOLD YOU
TO THAT 4 MINUTES.
REED: IT WAS ONLY
AN ESTIMATE, SIR.
ARCHER: HOW MANY TIMES
DO YOU THINK WE'VE DONE THIS?
REED: AT LEAST TWICE,
MAYBE MORE.
ARCHER: LET'S HOPE WE'VE
GOT IT DOWN BY NOW.
[ WHIRRING ]
THEY'RE CUTTING
THROUGH THE DOORS.
ARCHER: CONTROL ROOM.
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER: LET'S GET
THOSE DOORS OPEN.
ARCHER: NOW.
REED: I'D RECOMMEND
PUTTING MORE DISTANCE
BETWEEN US AND THAT SH--
ARCHER: NOW!
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
T'POL TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
THEY'VE NEUTRALIZED THE WARHEAD.
ARCHER: ON OUR WAY.
TRAVIS: SIR, IT'S GONE.
ARCHER: GONE?
IT DEMATERIALIZED. AND IT'S
NOT ABOARD THE THOLIAN SHIPS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THEY'RE DISENGAGING.
ARCHER: WHY DIDN'T
THEY FIRE ON US?
REED: GOOD QUESTION.
THEY MAY HAVE ONLY WANTED
THE VESSEL.
ARCHER: THE VULCANS?
T'POL: THEIR WARP DRIVE
IS DAMAGED,
BUT LIFE SUPPORT IS STABLE.
ARCHER: LET'S SEE IF WE CAN
GIVE THEM A HAND.
PREP A SHUTTLEPOD.
HAVE DR. PHLOX MEET US
IN LAUNCH BAY 1.
HOSHI: AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
A VULCAN TRANSPORT IS EN ROUTE
TO TOW THE TAL'KIR.
FORTUNATELY,
THERE WERE NO CASUALTIES.
OUR LONG-RANGE SCANNERS
SHOW NO SIGN
OF THOLIANS OR SULIBAN
IN OUR VICINITY.
TUCKER: I WISH WE'D HAD MORE
TIME TO EXPLORE THAT SHIP.
WHO KNOWS HOW MANY OTHER ROOMS
WERE DOWN THERE?
LOOKS LIKE THEY SENT
THE WHOLE KIT AND CABOODLE
BACK TO THE 31st CENTURY.
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE
TO SUPPORT THAT.
WELL, THERE'S NO EVIDENCE
TO CONTRADICT IT, EITHER.
WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND IS
HOW QUICKLY
EVERYTHING DISAPPEARED.
THAT BEACON WAS ONLINE
FOR LESS THAN A MINUTE.
YOU'RE FORGETTING THAT TIME
IS IRRELEVANT TO THESE PEOPLE.
IRRELEVANT?
IF THAT VESSEL
WAS FROM THE FUTURE,
WHOEVER SENT IT HAD PLENTY
OF TIME TO LOCATE THE SIGNAL
AND THEN TRAVEL BACK TO ANY
POINT IN TIME TO RETRIEVE IT.
HMM.
WELL, UNFORTUNATELY, TIME ISN'T
IRRELEVANT IN MY ENGINE ROOM.
I'VE GOT REPAIRS TO FINISH.
SEE YOU LATER.
ARCHER: MM-HMM.
TUCKER: SUBCOMMANDER.
I'M GOING TO CONTACT
THE HIGH COMMAND,
APOLOGIZE FOR THE TROUBLE
WE CAUSED THEM.
AS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE TAL'KIR POINTED OUT,
A SHIP CAN BE REPLACED.
I ALSO NEED TO THANK THEM
FOR HELPING US OUT.
I'M SURE THE GESTURE
WOULD BE APPRECIATED.
THE HIGH COMMAND HAS ASKED ME
TO PREPARE A REPORT
ON THIS INCIDENT
WITH YOUR PERMISSION.
BY ALL MEANS.
I WONDER IF THEY'LL BELIEVE
THAT HUMANS AND VULCANS
WILL BE...
SWAPPING CHROMOSOMES ONE DAY?
THEY'RE MORE LIKELY
TO BELIEVE IN TIME TRAVEL.