[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
HOSHI: Enterprise
to Shuttlepod 1.
Enterprise to Shuttlepod 1.
Captain Archer, please respond.
ENTERPRISE TO SHUTTLEPOD 1.
CAPTAIN ARCHER, PLEASE RESPOND.
LIEUTENANT?
THEY TOOK SOME WEAPONS FIRE.
MAIN POWER'S OFFLINE.
GRAVITY PLATING, LIFE SUPPORT.
BIOSIGNS?
NONE.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
TRIP AND I HAVE LEFT KETO-ENOL,
WHERE WE HAD
A SUCCESSFUL FIRST CONTACT
WITH THE ENOLIANS.
WE ALSO FOUND TIME
TO SQUEEZE IN A LITTLE R&amp;R.
HOSHI: THERE'S ONLY
ONE MORE LOG ENTRY AFTER THAT.
SOMETHING ABOUT A PAN ZAN MATCH.
PAN ZAN?
IT'S A SPORTING EVENT.
THE CAPTAIN SAID IT WAS
THE CLOSEST THING TO WATER POLO
HE'D SEEN SINCE WE LEFT EARTH.
SENSOR LOGS?
TOO BADLY DAMAGED
TO BE MUCH HELP.
IF I MAY, I'VE BEEN RUNNING
A FORENSIC ANALYSIS.
THERE ARE TRACES OF HUMAN BLOOD
ON THE DECK AND BULKHEADS --
BOTH THE CAPTAIN'S
AND COMMANDER TUCKER'S.
LIEUTENANT REED
BELIEVES THEY WERE ABDUCTED.
IF THEY WERE, THEY DIDN'T
GO WITHOUT A FIGHT.
SET A COURSE FOR KETO-ENOL.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
CAPTAIN.
ARE YOU IN CHARGE HERE?
IF YOU'RE NOT, I NEED TO SPEAK
TO YOUR SUPERIOR OFFICER.
[ GRUNTING ]
CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: I'M OKAY.
MAN: I'D STAY QUIET
IF I WERE YOU.
THE GUARDS DON'T LIKE QUESTIONS.
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE THEY'RE TAKING US?
I HEARD SOMETHING ABOUT CANAMAR.
I ASSUME THAT'S
WHERE WE'RE GOING.
ALIEN: IT'S A PENAL COLONY.
IS THIS HOW
YOUR JUSTICE SYSTEM WORKS?
SHIP PEOPLE OFF TO PRISON
WITHOUT A TRIAL?
THERE'S A PROCESSING STATION
IN ORBIT.
YOU'LL BE TRIED, SENTENCED,
AND SENT DOWN TO THE SURFACE.
WHAT IF YOU'RE NOT GUILTY?
WE'RE ALL GUILTY
AS FAR AS THEY'RE CONCERNED.
WHY DID THEY TAKE YOU?
THEY THINK WE'RE SMUGGLERS.
I WOULDN'T WANT
TO BE ACCUSED OF SMUGGLING.
THEY'LL PROBABLY
MAKE AN EXAMPLE OF YOU.
WE'RE ON AN EXPLORATORY MISSION.
WE BELIEVE OUR CAPTAIN
AND CHIEF ENGINEER
WERE ABDUCTED
AFTER VISITING YOUR PLANET.
ABDUCTED BY WHOM?
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE'RE THE BUSIEST
TRADING OUTPOST IN THIS SYSTEM.
WE GET THOUSANDS OF VISITORS
EVERY DAY.
UNFORTUNATELY, THAT ATTRACTS
JUST AS MANY THIEVES
AND SMUGGLERS.
AS YOU MIGHT IMAGINE,
MY OFFICERS ARE KEPT
QUITE BUSY.
I WISH I COULD HELP YOU.
LET US SEND YOU
THEIR DESCRIPTIONS.
PERHAPS YOU COULD FIND OUT
IF ANY OF YOUR OFFICERS
HAVE SEEN THEM.
ANYTHING ELSE ON THE MENU?
ALIEN: IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT,
GIVE IT TO ME.
I LIKE IT JUST FINE.
EAT YOUR OWN.
YOU DON'T LISTEN TOO WELL.
THEN WHY DON'T YOU
SAVE YOURSELF THE TROUBLE
AND STOP TALKING TO ME?
[ GROWLS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANS ]
THANKS.
[ GRUNTS ]
YOU SHOULD BE CAREFUL
WITH THE NAUSICAANS.
NASTY TEMPERS.
THANKS FOR THE ADVICE.
WHAT WERE YOU SMUGGLING?
LATINUM?
ENOLIAN SPICE WINE?
WE'RE NOT SMUGGLERS.
I'M THE CHIEF ENGINEER OF
A STARSHIP, AND HE'S MY CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN OF A STARSHIP.
INTERESTING.
I SHOULD HAVE TRIED THAT
WHEN THEY TOOK ME.
IT MIGHT HAVE HELPED.
"CAPTAIN ZOUMAS."
A PATROL SHIP INTERCEPTED
THEIR SHUTTLE
AS IT WAS LEAVING ORBIT.
T'POL: WHERE ARE THEY?
ON BOARD ONE OF OUR TRANSPORTS.
THEY WERE CARRYING
WHAT APPEARED TO BE CONTRABAND,
SO THEY WERE TAKEN INTO CUSTODY.
ARE YOUR PATROLS IN THE HABIT
OF ARRESTING INNOCENT PEOPLE?
SMUGGLING IS RAMPANT
IN THIS SYSTEM.
MY MEN HAVE ORDERS
TO BOARD UNFAMILIAR VESSELS.
MISTAKES CAN BE MADE.
YOU CERTAINLY MADE ONE
THIS TIME.
I'VE CONTACTED THE TRANSPORT.
THEY'RE EXPECTING YOU.
THESE ARE THE COORDINATES.
I TRUST YOU'LL ACCOMPANY US
TO ENSURE THERE ARE
NO FURTHER MISTAKES.
TUCKER: WHAT IF ENTERPRISE
DOESN'T FIND THE SHUTTLEPOD?
HOPEFULLY,
THERE'LL BE A JUDGE OR...
SOMEONE ON THAT PROCESSING
STATION WE CAN TALK TO.
AND IF NOT?
YOU MIGHT WANT TO MAKE FRIENDS
WITH THAT NAUSICAAN.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
ARE YOU ARCHER?
YOU'RE BEING RELEASED.
SHIP'S COMING TO RETRIEVE YOU.
NAUSICAAN: RELEASED? WHY?
TUCKER: WE'RE NOT CRIMINALS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
HOW MUCH DID THEY PAY YOU
TO LET THEM GO?
QUIET.
I'M INNOCENT, TOO.
I'LL PAY YOU.
I SAID QUIET.
WE'RE ALL INNOCENT!
HOW MUCH?!
[ GRUNTS ]
THAT'S ENOUGH!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
PRISONER: RELEASE ME!
I CAN HELP YOU!
KEEP STILL! ALL OF YOU.
IF YOU WANT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
[ RESTRAINTS CLICK ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I TOLD YOU WE NEEDED THE PILOT.
HE'S ALIVE.
DOES HE LOOK LIKE HE'S IN
ANY CONDITION TO FLY THIS SHIP?
HE TRIED TO GET A WEAPON.
JUST WATCH THEM!
WHAT ABOUT THE REST OF US?
YOU'LL BE RELEASED SOON ENOUGH.
WHEN?!
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
BE PATIENT.
YOU'LL FIND OUT.
I'M SURE WE'RE ALL GRATEFUL
FOR YOUR COURAGEOUS EFFORT,
BUT WE'VE BEEN IN THESE
RESTRAINTS FOR THREE DAYS.
-COULDN'T YOU JUST --
-QUIET!
I'LL SEE IF I CAN
ACCESS NAVIGATION.
ARCHER: YOU EVER FLY
A WARP SHIP BEFORE?
IT'S HARDER THAN YOU THINK.
TUCKER: HE'S RIGHT.
YOU HIT THE WRONG CONTROL,
YOU COULD OVERLOAD
THE PLASMA MANIFOLDS
OR SHUT DOWN THE ANTIMATTER
CONTAINMENT FIELD.
WE'D ALL END UP A CLOUD
OF IONIZED GAS.
YOU'RE A PILOT?
A DAMN GOOD ONE.
I'M A SMUGGLER, REMEMBER?
COME WITH ME.
MY PARTNER'S AN ENGINEER.
I COULD USE HIS HELP.
JUST YOU.
[ BEEPING ]
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A PILOT.
EVERY SHIP'S DIFFERENT.
JUST GIVE ME SOME TIME.
THESE LOOK LIKE
LANDING THRUSTERS.
ATTITUDE CONTROL.
WARP STABILIZERS.
NAVIGATION?
NAVIGATION.
THERE'S A BINARY SYSTEM
4 LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE.
THIS ONE?
-SET A COURSE.
-WHICH PLANET?
I'LL TELL YOU THAT
WHEN WE GET THERE.
WE'RE NOT GONNA GET VERY FAR
IN A STOLEN PRISON TRANSPORT.
JUST GET ME TO THAT SYSTEM.
[ ENGINES WHIRRING ]
GUARD: YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
IF HE DIES.
IF YOU GET HIM
MEDICAL ATTENTION,
IT'LL WORK IN YOUR FAVOR.
I'LL TELL THE MAGISTRATE
YOU SHOWED COMPASSION.
[ GROANING ]
THE GUARD SAID YOU WERE
GOING TO BE RELEASED.
WHY?
BECAUSE WE'RE INNOCENT.
I HAVE FRIENDS WHO WANTED TO
KEEP DOING BUSINESS WITH ME.
THEY MADE A FEW
DISCREET PAYMENTS, AND NOW...
I'M INNOCENT.
I WOULD HAVE BEEN
OFF THIS SHIP BY NOW
IF YOU HADN'T STAGED
YOUR LITTLE REVOLT.
I HOPE YOU'VE
THOUGHT THIS THROUGH.
EVERY DETAIL.
I'M CURIOUS.
HOW'D YOU GET OUT
OF THOSE RESTRAINTS?
YOU COULDN'T HAVE A LOCKPICK.
THE GUARDS WOULD HAVE FOUND IT.
WOULD THEY?
SUBDERMAL IMPLANTS.
THEY DEPOLARIZE
TRIBURNIUM ALLOYS.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
YOU WERE GOING TO NEED THEM?
I SERVED SEVEN YEARS ON CANAMAR
BEFORE I ESCAPED.
I DON'T INTEND TO GO BACK.
SO, I LEFT PREPARED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'VE GOT
IN MIND, BUT I'M INVOLVED NOW.
I DON'T WANT TO GO TO CANAMAR
ANY MORE THAN YOU DO.
IF WE RUN INTO TROUBLE,
MY PARTNER COULD HELP.
WHAT IS THAT?
SUBSPACE TRANSCEIVER.
I HOPE YOU'RE NOT TRYING
TO SEND A MESSAGE.
I'M TAKING IT OFFLINE.
IT LEAVES A SUBSPACE SIGNATURE
EVEN WHEN IT'S NOT TRANSMITTING.
SOMEONE COULD TRACK US.
NOW IT'S OFFLINE.
[ BEEPING ]
I'M PICKING UP
AN AUTOMATED DISTRESS SIGNAL.
THAT'S ONE OF OUR FREQUENCIES.
YOUR TRANSPORT VESSEL?
WE HAVE HUNDREDS OF SHIPS.
I DON'T KNOW THE SIGNATURES
FOR EVERY ONE.
THE SIGNAL ORIGINATED NEAR
OUR RENDEZVOUS COORDINATES,
BUT THEY'VE STOPPED
TRANSMITTING.
TRY HAILING THEM.
NO RESPONSE.
INCREASE OUR SPEED TO WARP 4.2.
WE'RE STILL SEVERAL HOURS AWAY,
BUT WE HAVE PATROL SHIPS
IN THAT AREA.
CONTACT THEM.
ZOUMAS: HAVE YOU EVER TRIED
TOJAL?
TUCKER: WHAT?
ZOUMAS: THERE'S NOTHING LIKE IT,
BUT YOU HAVE TO EAT IT
BEFORE IT COOLS.
-OTHERWISE IT'LL CONGEAL.
-SOUNDS TERRIFIC.
IT'S THE FIRST THING I'M GONNA
HAVE WHEN WE'RE OFF THIS SHIP.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
THEY'RE TAKING US?
ASK HIM.
I'LL JUST WAIT AND SEE.
THE ENOLIANS WON'T
STOP LOOKING FOR US.
WE'LL BE FUGITIVES.
I WAS THINKING OF HAVING
MY FACE RECONFIGURED.
THERE'S A SURGEON
ON BURALA PRIME WHO CAN DO IT.
HE COULD HELP YOU, AS WELL.
I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES
WITH MY OWN FACE.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
TO BURALA PRIME?
CAN'T SAY I HAVE.
IF YOU EVER GO,
AVOID THE POLAR ISLANDS.
THE PEOPLE ARE FRIENDLY,
BUT THE COLD IS UNBEARABLE.
NOTHING BUT ICE AND GLACIERS.
I WAS STRANDED THERE
FOR THREE MONTHS
WHEN SOME COLLEAGUES OF MINE
DECIDED TO LEAVE WITHOUT ME.
IMAGINE THAT.
THE DAY I GOT LOST,
THAT WAS THE WORST.
14 HOURS -- IT TOOK ME 14 HOURS
TO FIND MY WAY BACK
TO THE OUTPOST.
I LOST THREE TOES TO FROSTBITE.
I'VE WALKED WITH A SLIGHT LIMP
EVER SINCE,
NOT THAT YOU'D NOTICE.
I'M GONNA GET THAT SURGEON TO DO
SOME WORK ON MY FOOT, AS WELL.
MAYBE HE CAN REPLACE
THE MISSING TOES.
EXCUSE ME.
CAN I CHANGE SEATS?
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'M SURPRISED WE HAVEN'T
CROSSED PATHS BEFORE.
WE'RE NEW TO THIS REGION.
WE USED TO WORK MOSTLY
IN THE SOL SYSTEM.
SOL?
IT'S OUR SUN.
OUR HOMEWORLD IS CALLED EARTH.
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
TWO VESSELS
APPROACHING FROM AFT.
LET ME SEE THEM.
ENOLIAN PATROL SHIPS.
THEY'VE FOUND US.
MORE QUICKLY THAN I EXPECTED.
WHEN YOU WERE TAKING
THE TRANSCEIVER OFFLINE,
YOU DIDN'T ACTIVATE IT
ACCIDENTALLY?
YOU THINK I SENT
A DISTRESS CALL?
I TOLD YOU WE SHOULD HAVE
GOTTEN RID OF THIS SHIP.
IT'S TOO EASY TO TRACK.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
DO THE SAME!
THOSE ARE HEAVILY ARMED
PATROL SHIPS.
WE'RE ONLY A TRANSPORT.
WE HAVE WEAPONS -- USE THEM!
WE'RE OUTGUNNED!
I'D RATHER TAKE MY CHANCES
ON CANAMAR.
AND I'D RATHER NOT.
NOW CHARGE THE WEAPONS.
THEY'RE TARGETING OUR ENGINES.
RETURN FIRE!
NO.
I'M WARNING YOU...
WE DON'T HAVE THE FIREPOWER.
IF WE ATTACK THOSE SHIPS,
THEY'LL DESTROY US.
I THINK I CAN GET US
OUT OF THIS...
BUT I'LL NEED TUCKER'S HELP.
[ GRUNTS ]
OH!
WHAT'S HAPPENING?!
IF THOSE ARE PATROL SHIPS,
YOU'RE GOING TO BE RECAPTURED.
SHOULDN'T WE BE GETTING
TO THE ESCAPE PODS?
THE NEXT PERSON WHO SPEAKS
GOES OUT THE AIRLOCK!
HE NEEDS TO CONCENTRATE.
TRIP, WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
ALMOST THERE!
LET US GO! I DON'T WANT TO DIE
TIED UP LIKE AN ANIMAL!
AAH!
[ GROANS ]
READY WHEN YOU ARE!
CEASE FIRE!
WE SURRENDER.
Pressurize your docking port
and prepare to be boarded,
or our next shot
will breach your hull.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
NOW!
THE PLASMA VENTS ARE OPEN!
THEY'VE TAKEN DAMAGE.
PROPULSION IS DOWN
ON BOTH SHIPS.
LOCK WEAPONS.
WE SHOULD GET OUT OF HERE
WHILE WE CAN.
-TARGET THEIR WARP REACTORS!
-THERE'S NO NEED.
AS SOON AS THEY
REPAIR THEIR DAMAGE,
THEY'LL COME AFTER US AGAIN.
DO YOU THINK THE ENOLIANS
ARE JUST GOING TO GIVE UP
IF WE DESTROY
TWO OF THEIR SHIPS?
ALL I'M WANTED FOR IS SMUGGLING.
I DON'T NEED TO ADD
MURDER CHARGES TO IT.
LET ME GET US OUT OF HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
IS THIS REALLY NECESSARY?
I JUST SAVED YOUR SKIN,
AND YOU STILL DON'T TRUST ME?
DO YOU KNOW HOW MUCH POWER FLOWS
THROUGH THOSE PLASMA CIRCUITS?
HOW MUCH?
A LOT.
I COULD HAVE BEEN ELECTROCUTED.
AH, THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
IS SAY THANKS.
THANKS.
THAT WAS NICE.
IT REMINDS ME
OF THE TIME I WAS --
SHUT UP!
BOTH OUR SHIPS WERE DISABLED
BEFORE THE TRANSPORT ESCAPED.
MY SUPERIORS DON'T WANT OUR
PATROLS TAKING ANY MORE CHANCES.
THEY'VE ISSUED ORDERS
TO DESTROY THE PRISON TRANSPORT.
ARE YOUR SUPERIORS AWARE
THAT THERE ARE
TWO INNOCENT HUMANS ABOARD?
THEY'RE MORE CONCERNED WITH
THE MAN WHO PLANNED THIS ESCAPE.
THEY WERE ABLE
TO MATCH HIS VOICE-PRINT
TO A PRISONER
NAMED KURODA LOR-EHN.
HE WAS RESPONSIBLE FOR MANY
CRIMES, SOME OF THEM BRUTAL.
THEY'RE DETERMINED TO STOP HIM.
AND WE'RE DETERMINED
TO GET OUR PEOPLE BACK.
THEN I SUGGEST YOU FIND THEM
BEFORE OUR PATROLS DO.
THAT WAS A CLEVER TRICK,
IGNITING THE PLASMA.
I USED IT ONCE BEFORE...
OUTRUNNING A CUSTOMS VESSEL
NEAR CORIDAN.
YOU OBVIOUSLY RAN OUT
OF CLEVER TRICKS.
OTHERWISE YOU WOULDN'T BE HERE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
EVERY SHIP LEAVING KETO-ENOL
WAS BEING BOARDED AND SEARCHED.
TO GET THROUGH THE CHECKPOINT,
I SAID I WAS A STARSHIP CAPTAIN
AND TUCKER WAS MY ENGINEER.
I MADE QUITE A POINT
ABOUT HOW I WAS ON A PEACEFUL
MISSION OF EXPLORATION.
THEY DIDN'T BELIEVE YOU?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THEY TURNED OUR SHUTTLE
INSIDE OUT...
FOUND MY CARGO,
AND WE WOUND UP HERE.
MY GOOD FORTUNE.
YOU SHOULD CONSIDER
COMING WITH US.
YOUR PARTNER, TOO.
DOING WHAT?
I HAVE SOME BUSINESS
I WASN'T ABLE TO FINISH
BEFORE I WAS ARRESTED.
IT COULD BE PROFITABLE.
I'M A SMUGGLER.
I'M NOT GOOD AT MUCH ELSE.
TRUST ME,
YOU'LL BE VERY INTERESTED
WHEN YOU FIND OUT
WHAT I HAVE IN MIND.
IT'S NOT AS IF I HAVE A LOT
OF OPTIONS RIGHT NOW.
BUT IF WE'RE GOING TO
WORK TOGETHER...
I'D LIKE TO KNOW
WHERE WE'RE HEADED.
THE FOURTH PLANET.
THERE'S A TRADING OUTPOST
CALLED TAMAAL.
AND THEN?
A SHIP'S GOING TO MEET US THERE.
THIS TRANSPORT
DRAWS TOO MUCH ATTENTION.
ZOUMAS: ONCE YOU GET PAST
THE TEXTURE,
THEY REALLY
DON'T TASTE THAT BAD.
THE FUN PART IS KEEPING THEM
IN YOUR MOUTH.
THEY JUMP AROUND UNTIL YOU
CRUNCH DOWN ON THEM --
ENOUGH!
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
NO. I LOVE HEARING HOW DELICIOUS
MELVARAN MUD FLEAS ARE
OR ABOUT THE TIME YOU SPENT TWO
HOURS WITH AN ORION SLAVE GIRL
OR THE MIRACLES DOCTORS
CAN PERFORM THESE DAYS,
GETTING RID OF FLUVIAN FUNGUS.
WELL, WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I WANT TO HEAR YOUR STORIES?
I HAVEN'T TOLD YOU ANY!
YOU WON'T LET ME
GET A WORD IN EDGEWISE!
I CAN'T EVEN PUT MY FINGERS
IN MY EARS.
10 MINUTES --
THAT'S ALL I'M ASKING.
JUST 10 MINUTES OF SILENCE.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
I WAS BEING SO ANNOYING.
WE SEEMED TO BE
GETTING ALONG SO WELL.
I JUST THOUGHT IT MIGHT BE NICE
TO HAVE A PLEASANT CONVERSATION
BEFORE I SPEND THE NEXT 10 YEARS
ON A PENAL COLONY.
LOOK...
I'M SORRY I SNAPPED AT YOU.
BUT THIS ISN'T EXACTLY
THE BEST PLACE TO SOCIALIZE.
THIS THRUSTER ASSEMBLY
TOOK A LOT OF DAMAGE.
WE SHOULD HAVE TUCKER
TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
DON'T BOTHER.
YOU'RE NOT THE ONE
WHO HAS TO FLY THIS THING.
IT WON'T BE FLYING MUCH LONGER.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
YOU HAVEN'T EATEN FOR TWO DAYS.
I CAN WAIT.
DON'T BE A FOOL.
I SAID I'M NOT HUNGRY!
[ DOOR OPENS ]
PRISON RATIONS!
IT'S BETTER THAN NOTHING.
YOU OBVIOUSLY NEVER SPENT TIME
ON A PENAL COLONY.
I WAS 14 WHEN I FIRST
TASTED THOSE RATIONS.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH
FOR ONE LIFETIME.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU STARTED
YOUR CAREER EARLY.
I WAS YOUNG.
BUT I WAS NO CRIMINAL.
NO?
MY FATHER AND I WERE WORKING AT
A TRANSPORT YARD ON KETO-ENOL.
THE SUPERVISOR ACCUSED ME
OF STEALING A BRACE OF LATINUM.
I HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH IT,
BUT THEY COULDN'T FIND
ANYONE ELSE TO BLAME.
I WAS SENTENCED
TO FIVE YEARS AT DURONOM.
THAT SOUNDS PRETTY SEVERE.
ENOLIAN GUARDS ARE KNOWN
FOR THEIR SEVERITY.
HAVEN'T YOU SEEN THAT BY NOW?
[ CHUCKLES ]
I LEARNED FAR MORE IN PRISON
THAN MY FATHER
COULD HAVE EVER TAUGHT ME.
AFTER I WAS RELEASED, I CHOSE
TO PUT MY NEW SKILLS TO USE.
I SUPPOSE I SHOULD BE GRATEFUL.
IF IT WASN'T
FOR THE ENOLIAN GUARD,
MY LIFE...WOULD HAVE BEEN
QUITE DULL.
WELCOME TO TAMAAL.
WHERE ARE YOUR FRIENDS?
THEY'LL BE HERE.
DO YOU HAVE LANDING COORDINATES?
WE'RE NOT LANDING.
THEY'RE GOING TO DOCK WITH US.
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?
ARE YOU GOING TO LET THEM
GO TO PRISON?
NO.
BEFORE WE LEAVE,
YOU'RE GOING TO SET THIS SHIP
ON A DECAYING ORBIT.
IT'LL BE INCINERATED.
AS FAR AS ANYONE
WILL BE ABLE TO TELL,
WE CRASHED TRYING TO LAND.
WHY KILL ALL THESE PEOPLE?
JUST LEAVE THEM.
NO ONE WILL BE LOOKING FOR US
IF THEY THINK WE'RE DEAD.
IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT, YOU CAN
ALWAYS GO BACK TO YOUR SEAT.
I MAY NOT KNOW
HOW TO FLY THIS SHIP,
BUT I'M SURE I CAN FIGURE OUT
HOW TO CRASH IT.
[ BEEPING ]
THE TRANSPORT'S
DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
IT'S ENTERED A BINARY SYSTEM.
IT LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE HEADING
FOR THE FOURTH PLANET.
ENOLIAN: TAMAAL --
IT'S A LARGE TRADING OUTPOST
WITH OVER TWO MILLION
INHABITANTS.
REED: A GOOD PLACE
TO GET LOST IN THE CROWD.
DROP TO IMPULSE.
TAKE US INTO THE SYSTEM.
ANY HUMAN BIOSIGNS?
TWO. IT'S THEM.
I RECOMMEND WE USE THE
TRANSPORTER ONCE WE'RE IN RANGE.
YOU'RE FORGETTING
THAT'S A PRISON SHIP.
IT'S HEAVILY SHIELDED.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
THE DOCKING HATCH WAS DAMAGED
BY THE PATROL SHIPS.
KURODA WANTS TUCKER
TO SEE IF HE CAN REPAIR IT.
NICE OF YOU TO VISIT.
WHO ARE WE DOCKING WITH?
YOUR GUESS IS AS GOOD AS MINE.
HE'S TAKING US OFF ON A SHUTTLE.
THEN HE PLANS TO CRASH THE SHIP.
I HOPE YOU'VE GOT
SOMETHING ELSE IN MIND.
WE CAN'T WAIT FOR ENTERPRISE.
WE'VE GOT TO TRY
TO TAKE CONTROL.
THINK YOU CAN HANDLE HIM?
YEAH, PIECE OF CAKE.
[ BEEPING ]
THERE'S A SMALL VESSEL
DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
PATROL SHIP?
REED: I DON'T THINK SO.
FOUR BIOSIGNS.
THEY'RE ALL ENOLIAN.
IT'S NOT ONE OF OUR SHIPS.
MAGNIFY.
WHERE'S IT HEADING?
THE FOURTH PLANET.
HOSHI: THEY'RE TRYING TO HAIL
THE PRISON TRANSPORT.
THEY'RE NOT GETTING A RESPONSE.
THEY MAY HAVE COME
TO RESCUE KURODA.
HOW HEAVILY ARMED IS IT?
FORE AND AFT PARTICLE CANNONS --
NOTHING WE CAN'T HANDLE.
MY FRIENDS WILL BE HERE SOON.
LAY IN A DESCENT COURSE.
THEIR SHIP MIGHT BE BIG ENOUGH
TO HOLD EVERYONE HERE.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE THEM ALONG?
WE HAVE ALREADY DISCUSSED THIS!
TRIP...
how's that docking port coming?
[ GRUNTS ]
[ PANTING ]
I NEED A MINUTE.
[ SIGHS ]
IT'S A BIG JOB.
DO YOUR BEST.
[ SIGHS ]
LISTEN...I KNOW WE KIND OF
GOT OFF ON THE WRONG FOOT.
NO HARD FEELINGS.
BUT NOW THAT WE'RE FRIENDS,
I COULD USE A HAND.
YOU'RE THE ENGINEER.
TRUE.
BUT I'M HAVING TROUBLE
GETTING THE INTAKE VALVE OPEN.
I GUESS I DON'T HAVE
THE MUSCLE FOR IT.
UNLESS I'M MISTAKEN, KURODA
WANTS THIS HATCH REPAIRED.
THAT ONE -- IF YOU COULD
TURN IT COUNTERCLOCKWISE.
DOWN A LITTLE MORE.
IT'S GOT TO GO
AT LEAST 90 DEGREES.
[ GRUNTING ]
THAT'S IT.
YOU ALMOST GOT IT.
PRISONER:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
ZOUMAS: THEY SAID
THEY WERE GOING TO LET US GO!
THEY LIED. THEY'RE PLANNING
TO KILL YOU -- ALL OF YOU.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU'RE GOING TO GET US
SENT TO CANAMAR!
KEEP IT DOWN!
[ ALARM BLARING ]
STAY HERE.
WATCH OUT!
DO YOU KNOW HOW TO REPAIR
THAT DOCKING HATCH?
IT'S NOT EASY.
WE'RE IN A DECAYING ORBIT!
SHOOT ME, AND YOU'LL DIE
WITH THE OTHERS.
GET TO WORK.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
KILL THESE PEOPLE.
MOVE!
[ GROANING ]
YOU SHOULD THANK ME.
WHAT?
WHERE'S ARCHER?
HE'S WITH THEM,
REPAIRING THE DOCKING HATCH.
THEY SAID THERE'S A SHUTTLE
COMING FOR US.
I'M SORRY I HAD TO INTERVENE,
BUT YOU DIDN'T GIVE ME
MUCH CHOICE.
YOU'RE LUCKY
THEY DIDN'T KILL YOU.
KURODA WAS FURIOUS.
BUT EVERYTHING'S FINE NOW.
THEY'RE GOING TO SET US FREE.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
[ RUMBLING ]
THEY'VE DOCKED.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
AAH!
I SEE MY MESSAGE GOT THROUGH.
LOUD AND CLEAR, SIR.
CAPTAIN?
WOULD YOU MIND?
WHO ARE THESE PEOPLE?
THIS WILL OPEN THE RESTRAINTS.
GET EVERYONE ON THAT SHUTTLE!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
FREE ME.
LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
COME ON!
-KEEP MOVING!
-COME ON!
LET'S GO. LET'S GO.
WE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
LET'S GO, EVERYBODY.
COME ON. MOVE OUT, MOVE OUT.
GO!
GO, GO NOW!
LET'S GO!
DON'T LEAVE ANYONE BEHIND.
GO, GO, GO.
COME ON.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
[ BEEPING ]
ANYTHING I CAN DO?
UNLESS YOU HAVE
A SPARE THRUSTER ASSEMBLY.
-IS EVERYONE OFF?
-JUST ABOUT.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
CAPTAIN!
TRAVIS SAYS HE CAN'T MAINTAIN
THE DOCKING SEAL MUCH LONGER.
HE WON'T HAVE TO!
LET'S GO!
[ GRUNTS ]
WE NEED TO BREAK ORBIT!
IT'S TOO LATE!
WE'VE LOST THRUSTERS!
YOU'RE LYING!
WE'VE GOT TO GET OUT!
[ SCREAMS ]
KURODA!
IT'S OVER!
I WON'T GO BACK!
IT'S NOW OR NEVER, SIR!
[ PANTING ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
WE'VE GOT SOME MEN IN THERE
WHO COULD USE YOUR HELP.
-AND YOU?
-I'LL BE FINE.
ON BEHALF
OF THE ENOLIAN GOVERNMENT,
I'D LIKE TO EXTEND OUR APOLOGIES
FOR THIS INCONVENIENCE.
MY SUPERIORS WILL WANT --
TRIP.
UH, CAPTAIN...
CAPTAIN, MY SUPERIORS WILL WANT
A REPORT ON WHAT HAPPENED.
I'LL GIVE YOU ONE RIGHT NOW.
KURODA'S DEAD, THE OTHER
11 PRISONERS ARE UNDER GUARD.
AS YOU'RE AWARE, MY ENGINEER
AND I WERE FALSELY ARRESTED.
WE ALMOST WOUND UP IN CANAMAR.
MAKES ME WONDER HOW MANY OTHERS
DON'T BELONG THERE.
YOU WANTED A REPORT?
YOU'VE GOT ONE.