[COMPUTER BEEPING]
REED: SENSORS CAN'T IDENTIFY
ITS HULL COMPOSITION.
THERE DOESN'T EVEN SEEM
TO BE A WARP SIGNATURE.
T'POL: IT'S APPROACHING
AT WARP 6.
ARCHER: HOW BIG IS IT?
REED: IT'S BIG--
MORE THAN 500 METERS ACROSS.
HOSHI: WE'RE IN VISUAL RANGE.
ARCHER: PUT IT UP.
LOOK FAMILIAR?
T'POL:
IT'S NOT IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
ARCHER: TRY HAILING THEM.
HOSHI: NO RESPONSE, SIR.
I'M NOT EVEN DETECTING
A TRANSCEIVER ONBOARD.
TRAVIS:
THEY'RE GAINING ON US, SIR.
REED: WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA
BEND OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ARCHER: TACTICAL ALERT.
REED: WEAPONS
AREN'T CHARGING, SIR.
THEY'RE OFFLINE.
PHASE CANNONS, TORPEDOES.
TUCKER: TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE!
ARCHER: Go ahead.
TUCKER:
WHAT'S GOING ON, CAPTAIN?
THE ENGINES JUST WENT DOWN.
ARCHER: Warp or impulse?
TUCKER: BOTH.
ARCHER: HOLD ON, TRIP.
HAVE THEY DROPPED OUT OF WARP?
T'POL: THERE'S NO WAY TO TELL.
OUR SENSORS CAN'T
PENETRATE THEIR HULL.
ARCHER:
WHAT ABOUT OUR LIFE SUPPORT?
T'POL: FULLY OPERATIONAL.
ARCHER: THAT'S ONE PIECE
OF GOOD NEWS.
ANY BIO-SIGNS OUT THERE?
T'POL: NONE THAT I CAN DETECT.
ARCHER: ROTATE
THE DORSAL CAMERA.
HOLD IT THERE.
TILT UP ABOUT 30 DEGREES.
GET CLOSER.
T'POL: THE VAPOR DOESN'T CONTAIN
ANY ELEMENTS OUR SENSORS
CAN IDENTIFY.
ARCHER: ANY ATMOSPHERE?
T'POL: MOSTLY HELIUM,
TRACE AMOUNTS OF XENON.
ARCHER: PREP A SHUTTLEPOD.
TRIP, MEET ME AND MALCOLM
IN LAUNCH BAY 1.
TUCKER: Aye, sir.
ARCHER: YOU'RE IN CHARGE.
KEEP A CHANNEL OPEN.
REED: CAPTAIN.
LOOK AT THIS.
THE ATMOSPHERE'S CHANGING.
76% NITROGEN, 21% OXYGEN.
TUCKER: SOMEBODY SEEMS TO KNOW
WHAT WE LIKE TO BREATHE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE TEMPERATURE?
REED: 18 DEGREES.
TUCKER: FLORIDA IN NOVEMBER.
ARCHER:
LET'S SEE WHAT WE CAN FIND.
TUCKER: LOOK AT THAT.
REED: I'M NOT READING ANYTHING.
IT'S LIKE THEY'RE NOT THERE.
TUCKER:
THEY SURE LOOK THERE TO ME.
REED: IF THERE AREN'T
ANY LIFE-FORMS HERE,
THEN WHO MODIFIED
THE ATMOSPHERE?
ARCHER:
I DOUBT IT'S A COINCIDENCE.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: WE MAY NOT BE DETECTING
ANY BIO-SIGNS,
BUT THOSE THINGS
SURE LOOK ALIVE TO ME.
[TUCKER GASPS]
ARCHER: ARE YOU OK?
TRIP?
[PANTING]
TUCKER: WHOA.
WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED?
ARCHER: THAT'S WHAT I WAS
ABOUT TO ASK YOU.
TUCKER: I THINK I WAS UP
ON THE CEILING
WITH THOSE THINGS.
I WAS LOOKING DOWN
AT THE THREE OF US
BUT NOT WITH MY EYES.
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
ARCHER: WE SHOULD GET HIM
BACK TO THE SHIP.
TUCKER: I WAS IN TARPON SPRINGS,
TOO, SWIMMING WITH LISA.
SHE WAS AFRAID
IT WAS GETTING TOO DARK.
REED: UH, SOUNDS LIKE YOU
WERE DREAMING, COMMANDER.
TUCKER: I KNOW THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN A DREAM
AND SOMETHING
REALLY HAPPENING.
ARCHER: WE'RE 150 LIGHT-YEARS
FROM EARTH, TRIP.
ARCHER:
I'M TELLING YOU, I WAS THERE.
PHLOX:
I'M NOT DETECTING ANY PARASITES
OR LIFE-FORMS
OR, UH, WISPS OF SMOKE.
HE SEEMS
IN PERFECT WORKING ORDER.
ARCHER: HE SAID HE HAD
SOME KIND OF
OUT-OF-BODY EXPERIENCE.
TUCKER: AND DON'T
FORGET FLORIDA, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T CARE HOW FAR AWAY IT IS.
I WAS THERE.
PHLOX: IT'S A VERY
COMMON HALLUCINATION--
RETURNING TO A FAMILIAR PLACE.
TUCKER: WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE COMM?
YOU THREE TALKING ABOUT ME?
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
PHLOX: YOU'RE CLEAR, COMMANDER.
FREE TO GO.
TUCKER: THANKS, DOC.
ARCHER:
YOU SURE YOU'RE ALL RIGHT?
TUCKER: I'M FINE.
YOU CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW AMAZING IT WAS.
ARCHER: I'D PREFER TO KEEP
YOU IN SICK BAY FOR A FEW DAYS,
BUT I CAN'T AFFORD TO.
I NEED YOU TO GET THOSE ENGINES
BACK ONLINE.
TUCKER: I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
ARCHER: LET ME KNOW
IF YOU TAKE ANOTHER TRIP
TO TARPON BEACH.
TUCKER: TARPON SPRINGS.
I'LL KEEP YOU POSTED.
ARCHER: I WANT THOSE WEAPONS
BACK ONLINE, TOO.
REED: I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
IT'S LIKE WE'RE
IN THE BELLY OF THE BEAST.
T'POL: WE HAVE NO REASON
TO BELIEVE
THEIR MOTIVES ARE HOSTILE.
ARCHER: THEY'RE HOLDING
MY SHIP HOSTAGE.
T'POL: WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
ARCHER:
WE DON'T? LOOK OUT THERE.
DO YOU SEE ANY STARS?
OUR ENGINES ARE OFFLINE,
OUR WEAPONS.
SEEMS KIND OF HOSTILE TO ME.
T'POL: I SUPPOSE IT DEPENDS
ON HOW YOU LOOK AT IT.
ARCHER: IS THERE SOMETHING
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME ABOUT?
T'POL: ENSIGN SATO
IS TRYING TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THE LIFE-FORMS.
ARCHER: AND?
T'POL: NOTHING YET.
I'VE SPOKEN
TO A NUMBER OF OFFICERS.
THEY SAY THE CREW IS
CONCERNED BUT REMAINING CALM.
ARCHER: I'VE GOT TO GET THEM
OUT OF HERE.
ROSTOV: I TRIED REINITIALIZING
THE PLASMA FLOW,
BUT THE POWER GRID
ISN'T CHARGING.
COMMANDER?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, SIR?
CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING?
TUCKER: I'M FINE.
GOOD-BYE, SIR.
ROSTOV TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: Go ahead.
I'M SORRY TO BOTHER YOU, SIR,
BUT I THINK THERE MIGHT
BE SOMETHING WRONG
WITH COMMANDER TUCKER.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU MEAN, WRONG?
ROSTOV: HE WAS CONFUSED,
AND, UH,
SEEMED TO THINK
I WAS HIS SUPERIOR OFFICER.
ARCHER: I'LL BE RIGHT DOWN.
ROSTOV: He's not here, sir.
He left engineering.
ARCHER:
DID HE SAY WHERE HE WAS GOING?
ROSTOV: NO, SIR.
I'm afraid not, Captain.
ARCHER:
ARCHER TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
FIND HIM.
COMMANDER?
TUCKER:
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER III.
ARCHER: HUNGRY?
TUCKER: YES. IT'S ALL VERY GOOD.
HAVE YOU EVER TRIED THIS?
IT'S CALLED BREAD.
ARCHER:
YOU'VE NEVER EATEN IT BEFORE?
TUCKER: I'VE NEVER EATEN
ANYTHING BEFORE.
T'POL: WHERE'S COMMANDER TUCKER?
I'M HERE. CHARLES TUCKER III.
ARCHER: WHERE'S THE MAN
WHO USED TO BE CHARLES TUCKER?
TUCKER: HE'S EXPLORING
ANOTHER REALM--MY REALM.
BUT HE'LL BE BACK.
ARCHER: I WANT HIM BACK NOW.
TUCKER: PLEASE TRUST ME.
HE'S EXPERIENCING THINGS
HE NEVER THOUGHT HE COULD.
ARCHER: WHERE IS HE?
TUCKER:
IT'S NOT A QUESTION OF WHERE.
HE'S NO LONGER CORPOREAL.
BUT HE WILL BE AGAIN,
I ASSURE YOU.
REED: WHEN WE WERE OUTSIDE,
WE SAW A WISP OF VAPOR
PENETRATE HIM.
DID YOU HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH THAT?
TUCKER:
WISP. AN INTERESTING WORD.
WISP. WISP.
YES, I SUPPOSE YOU COULD
CALL US THAT. WISP.
ARCHER: WHERE DO YOU COME FROM?
TUCKER: WE LIVE IN SUBSPACE.
WE TRAVEL THROUGH IT.
WE'RE EXPLORERS, LIKE YOU.
ARCHER: WHY DID YOU TAKE
COMMANDER TUCKER?
TUCKER: IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE WE'VE ENCOUNTERED
CORPOREAL BEINGS.
AFTER WE PERFORMED THE FIRST
CROSSING WITH YOUR COMMANDER,
WE REALIZED WE WERE COMPATIBLE.
YOU'RE VERY INTERESTING--
TRAPPED IN BODIES
THAT NEED MAINTENANCE.
YOU HAVE GENDER.
YOU REQUIRE MATES TO REPRODUCE.
YOU EAT FOOD.
WE WERE LIKE YOU ONCE,
BUT WE EVOLVED.
NOW WE CAN LEARN
HOW OUR ANCESTORS LIVED.
ARCHER: I WANT MY CREWMAN,
AND I WANT MY SHIP RELEASED.
REED: CAPTAIN.
TUCKER: YOUR CREWMAN
WILL BE RETURNED.
YOU CLAIM TO BE AN EXPLORER,
CAPTAIN.
OPEN YOUR MIND
TO NEW POSSIBILITIES.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT TUCKER?
TUCKER:
I'VE ENJOYED MY TIME WITH YOU.
REED: SIR.
TUCKER: WOW.
ARCHER: WOW, WHAT?
TUCKER: I WAS RIDING
RIGHT ALONGSIDE HOPALONG CASSIDY
CHASING SOME BAD GUYS.
THEN I WAS WITH LISA AGAIN,
EXCEPT THIS TIME,
WE WERE SNOW SAILING
IN NEW ZEALAND.
THEN I WAS 8 YEARS OLD,
MAYBE 9,
PICKING UP LEAVES WITH MY DAD.
BUT IT WASN'T A DREAM, CAPTAIN.
IT WAS AS REAL
AS I'M SITTING HERE.
THEY TOLD ME YOU CAN TRY IT,
ANYONE ON THE CREW.
ARCHER: WHO TOLD YOU?
TUCKER: THEY DID--
THE--THE ONES I WAS WITH.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT YOU WERE
WITH HOPALONG CASSIDY
AND YOUR GIRLFRIEND.
[TUCKER CHUCKLING]
TUCKER: WELL, I WAS, BUT--
OH, IT'S HARD TO EXPLAIN.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT.
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
YOU ALL SHOULD TRY IT.
ARCHER: TAKE HIM TO SICK BAY.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN, I'M FINE.
ARCHER: WE'LL LET THE DOCTOR
DECIDE HOW FINE YOU ARE.
REED: COMMANDER.
ARCHER: SOMETHING SMELLS FUNNY.
T'POL: THEY'VE RELEASED THE SHIP
AND COMMANDER TUCKER.
THEY'VE DONE EVERYTHING
YOU'VE ASKED.
HAVE YOU CONSIDERED THEY MAY
HAVE BEEN TELLING THE TRUTH
WHEN THEY SAID THEY WERE
JUST CURIOUS ABOUT US?
ARCHER:
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
NOW THAT THE DOCTOR
HAS GIVEN TRIP
A CLEAN BILL OF HEALTH,
MY PRIMARY CONCERN
IS GETTING "ENTERPRISE"
OUT OF HERE.
BUT TRIP TELLS ME
IT'LL BE A WHILE
BEFORE HE CAN GET
THE ENGINES ONLINE.
FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL,
THESE LIFE-FORMS HAVE NO MASS.
NONCORPOREAL BEINGS--
THAT'S GOT TO BE A FIRST
FOR STARFLEET.
T'POL THINKS THEY JUST WANT
TO GET TO KNOW US.
MAYBE SHE'S RIGHT.
MAYBE I DON'T TRUST THEM
BECAUSE THEY'RE SO DIFFERENT.
I'D HATE TO THINK
THAT WAS THE CASE.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COMPUTER, PAUSE. COME IN.
PHLOX: I HOPE I'M NOT
DISTURBING YOU.
ARCHER: EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
PHLOX: I'M NOT CERTAIN.
ONE OF THOSE BEINGS
APPEARED IN SICK BAY
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
IT ENTERED ME RIGHT HERE.
BUT MY PHYSIOLOGY MUST NOT
HAVE BEEN COMPATIBLE.
IT LEFT ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
ARCHER:
ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE ALL RIGHT?
PHLOX: I'M FINE.
BUT IT WAS DISTURBING.
THE LIFE-FORM WAS TRYING
VERY HARD TO REACH ME.
CREWMAN:
I'M GOING TO "B" DECK.
REED: "B" DECK IS FINE.
ARE YOU A FEMALE?
CREWMAN: SIR?
REED: YOUR GENDER.
YOU ARE A FEMALE, CORRECT?
CREWMAN: LAST TIME I CHECKED.
REED: I AM A MALE.
CREWMAN: I'M AWARE
OF THAT, LIEUTENANT.
THERE SEEM TO BE A NUMBER
OF ANATOMICAL DIFFERENCES.
[CREWMAN SIGHS]
CREWMAN: SIR.
[DOOR CHIMES]
T'POL: COME IN.
REED: SUB-COMMANDER.
T'POL: IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
REED: YOU ARE VERY BEAUTIFUL.
ARE YOU AWARE THAT YOU ARE
THE MOST ATTRACTIVE WOMAN
ONBOARD THIS SHIP?
T'POL: DO YOU THINK
IT'S APPROPRIATE
FOR YOU TO BE HERE AT THIS HOUR?
REED: WOULD YOU MIND
TAKING OFF YOUR CLOTHING?
I'D LIKE TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT YOUR ANATOMY.
T'POL: HAVE YOU BEEN DRINKING?
REED:
IF WE ARE TO ENGAGE IN MATING,
IT WOULD BE EASIER
IF YOU DISROBED.
T'POL: T'POL TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: Go ahead.
T'POL: WOULD YOU
PLEASE COME TO MY QUARTERS
WITH A SECURITY TEAM?
ARCHER: We're on our way.
REED: ARE YOU AFRAID OF ME?
YOU SHOULDN'T BE.
T'POL:
I'M CAPABLE OF DEFENDING MYSELF.
REED: WHAT IS IT LIKE
BEING A FEMALE?
IS IT MUCH DIFFERENT?
T'POL: I WOULDN'T KNOW.
REED: IF YOU'D ALLOW
THE CROSSING, YOU'D FIND OUT.
T'POL: I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
REED: IF YOU CAME TO US,
YOU COULD EXPERIENCE
WHAT IT'S LIKE TO BE MALE.
WOULDN'T THAT BE
HELPFUL TO YOU?
T'POL: I'VE NEVER
THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
REED: YOU SHOULD.
WE'RE CAPABLE OF LETTING
YOU EXPERIENCE
ANYTHING YOU WISH FOR.
IT WOULD BE A SHAME...
NOT TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THAT.
T'POL:
THIS ISN'T LIEUTENANT REED.
ARCHER: ENOUGH!
HUMANS DON'T LIKE DOING THINGS
WITHOUT THEIR CONSENT.
WHEN ARE YOU PLANNING
TO RETURN MALCOLM REED?
REED: THAT DEPENDS.
ARCHER: OH, DOES IT?
LET'S SEE HOW MUCH
YOU ENJOY EXPERIENCING
THE HUMAN CONDITION
LOCKED IN REED'S QUARTERS.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
TUCKER: TUCKER.
ARCHER: They've got Malcolm.
I NEED THE SHIP
READY TO GO ON MY COMMAND.
TUCKER: They're gonna
give him back, aren't they?
ARCHER: WE'LL SEE.
TUCKER:
WHAT DID YOU DO WITH THE, UH--
ARCHER: A SECURITY DETAIL LOCKED
HIM IN MALCOLM'S QUARTERS.
GET IT DONE, TRIP.
TUCKER: RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
YOU HEARD HIM.
LET'S TRY TO PRIME
THE DEUTERIUM PUMPS
AND FIRE UP THE INJECTORS.
TUCKER: TUCKER TO ENSIGN COOK.
COOK: Yes, sir.
TUCKER: I NEED YOU AND TWO OTHER
ENGINEERS DOWN HERE RIGHT AWAY.
COOK: I'll see who I can find.
ROSTOV: COMMANDER!
TUCKER:
QUICKLY, PLEASE. TUCKER OUT.
SOMETHING WRONG?
RUN INTO A PROBLEM?
ROSTOV: PROBLEM?
NO, EVERYTHING'S FINE.
TUCKER: DID YOU HAVE ANY LUCK
PRIMING THE PUMPS?
ROSTOV:
I HAVE NO IDEA HOW TO DO THAT.
THIS ENGINE IS VERY COMPLEX.
TUCKER:
STAY HERE. I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
TUCKER TO THE CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD, TRIP.
TUCKER: It's Rostov, sir.
I think you need
to get Malcolm--
I MEAN WHOEVER'S
RUNNING SECURITY
DOWN HERE RIGHT AWAY.
ARCHER: HOSHI, GET A SECURITY
TEAM TO ENGINEERING.
HAVE THEM PUT CREWMAN ROSTOV
IN HIS QUARTERS.
HOSHI: AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE BEEN
GETTING REPORTS
FROM ALL OVER THE SHIP.
SOME OF THE CREW
ARE ACTING VERY STRANGE.
ARCHER: THEN WE'RE GOING TO NEED
MORE THAN ONE SECURITY TEAM.
FIND OUT WHO'S ACTING STRANGE
AND HAVE THEM CONFINED
TO THEIR QUARTERS.
TRAVIS: HOW DO WE KNOW
THE SECURITY OFFICERS ARE OK?
ARCHER: FOR THE MOMENT, WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE TO HOPE THEY ARE.
START WORKING ON A WAY
TO FIGURE OUT
WHO'S THEMSELVES AND WHO'S NOT.
MAYBE PHLOX CAN HELP YOU.
COOK: COMMANDER.
TUCKER: RUN INTO A PROBLEM?
COOK: NO, SIR.
JUST READY TO CALIBRATE
THE DILITHIUM MATRIX.
TUCKER: GREAT. WAIT
TILL I GIVE YOU THE SIGNAL.
HOSHI:
WE POLARIZED THE HULL PLATING
AS SOON AS WE DETECTED
THAT SHIP.
OBVIOUSLY IT DIDN'T DO ANY GOOD.
WHAT'S KEEPING THEM
FROM TAKING ALL OF US?
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
ARCHER: ARCHER.
TUCKER: YOU'VE GOT
IMPULSE ENGINES BACK, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: Thanks, Trip.
HOLD OUR POSITION.
HOSHI: I THOUGHT YOU SAID
WE NEEDED TO GET OUT OF HERE.
ARCHER: THEY'VE GOT MALCOLM
AND GOD KNOWS HOW MANY OTHERS.
UNTIL WE FIND A WAY
TO GET THEM BACK,
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE BIG SECRET?
T'POL: WE THOUGHT IT BEST NOT
TO DISCUSS THIS OVER THE COMM.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO'S BEEN TAKEN.
ARCHER: WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
PHLOX: IT WAS SIMPLER
THAN I THOUGHT.
ELEVATED ACETYLCHOLINE LEVELS
IN THE AUTONOMIC NERVOUS--
ARCHER: DOCTOR, WHATEVER YOU'VE
GOT, WE NEED TO PUT IT TO WORK.
PHLOX: THE SUB-COMMANDER
PROGRAMMED THE MEDICAL COMPUTER.
IT'S MODIFYING
THIS HAND-SCANNER AS WE SPEAK.
ARCHER: GET TO WORK
AS SOON AS YOU'RE READY.
TUCKER:
Tucker to Ensign Mayweather.
TRAVIS: GO AHEAD, SIR.
TUCKER: I'm a little
short-handed, Travis.
THINK I COULD GET YOU TO GO BACK
TO THE STARBOARD NACELLE
AND REPOLARIZE THE WARP COILS?
TRAVIS: NO PROBLEM, SIR.
TUCKER: Call me when you get
to the catwalk.
TRAVIS: I'M ON MY WAY.
T'POL: THERE ARE TWO HERE.
PHLOX:
ENSIGN COLE AND CREWMAN ROSSI.
TRAVIS: MAYWEATHER
TO THE BRIDGE.
ARCHER: Go ahead.
TRAVIS: ONE OF THOSE THINGS
JUST FOLLOWED ME
UP THE STARBOARD STRUT,
BUT WHEN I GOT INTO THE CATWALK,
IT DIDN'T COME THROUGH.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING KEEPING
IT FROM GETTING IN HERE.
ARCHER: THEN YOU BETTER STAY
WHERE YOU ARE.
TRAVIS: Aye, sir.
ARCHER:
ARCHER TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
TUCKER: YES, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER:
Is there some kind of shielding
IN THE NACELLES THAT MIGHT KEEP
THESE ALIENS FROM GETTING IN?
TUCKER: THE CATWALK'S
REINFORCED WITH OSMIUM ALLOY,
BUT IT'S HARD TO SAY
IF THAT WOULD DO IT.
ARCHER: Travis thinks it will.
I NEED YOU TO STOP
WHATEVER YOU'RE DOING
AND TRANSFER
ALL COMMAND FUNCTIONS
to the starboard catwalk.
We're going to have to get
everybody in there.
TUCKER: I'M ON IT.
ARCHER: I WANT YOU AND T'POL
TO GET THE CREW UP THERE
AS QUICKLY AS YOU CAN.
HOSHI.
HOSHI: IT WOULD BE BEST
IF THEY STAYED WHERE THEY WERE.
ARCHER: WHAT?
HOSHI: WE'RE OFFERING THEM
A GREAT OPPORTUNITY.
THEY MAY NEVER
GET ANOTHER CHANCE
TO EXPERIENCE EXISTENCE
AS WE DO.
ARCHER: SECURITY TO THE BRIDGE.
YOU'RE TAKING OVER MY CREW. WHY?
HOSHI: I UNDERSTAND HOW YOU
MAY BE FRIGHTENED BY ALL THIS--
LOSING YOUR SUBSTANCE,
EXISTING AS PERCEPTIVE ENERGY--
BUT YOU'LL BE GRATEFUL
ONCE YOU'VE MADE THE CROSSING,
I PROMISE YOU.
ARCHER: WE'RE KIND OF FOND
OF OUR SUBSTANCE.
WE'RE NOT VERY ANXIOUS
TO GIVE IT UP.
HOSHI: THOSE WHO'VE
PRECEDED YOU ARE SAFE AND HAPPY.
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: ARE YOU DOING THIS
FOR OUR BENEFIT OR FOR YOURS?
ESCORT ENSIGN SATO
TO HER QUARTERS.
HOSHI: YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: HOW MANY?
T'POL: 58, INCLUDING US.
ARCHER: AND OUTSIDE?
T'POL: 24 LOCKED IN
THEIR QUARTERS, AND DR. PHLOX.
ARCHER: YOU OK, TRAVIS?
TUCKER: I'M FINE, SIR.
THANK YOU.
ARCHER: TRIP?
TRAVIS: I SAW HIM DOWN NEAR
THE COMMAND COMPARTMENT.
ARCHER: THANKS.
T'POL: WE NEED TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT THESE LIFE-FORMS.
ARCHER: WHAT WE NEED IS TO GET
OUR PEOPLE BACK.
T'POL: IT'S ILLOGICAL
TO BELIEVE WE CAN DO THAT
WITHOUT LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE ALIENS' INTENTIONS.
ARCHER:
DO YOU HAVE SOMETHING IN MIND?
T'POL: I'D LIKE YOUR PERMISSION
TO LEAVE THE CATWALK.
ARCHER:
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE A CHANCE.
ONE OF THOSE THINGS
WOULD TAKE YOU
BEFORE YOU GOT BACK
TO THE SAUCER SECTION.
T'POL: NOT NECESSARILY.
IF A LIFE-FORM ATTEMPTS
TO EXCHANGE ITS CONSCIOUSNESS
WITH MINE,
I BELIEVE I CAN PREVENT IT.
ARCHER:
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK THAT?
NO OFFENSE, CAPTAIN,
BUT THE VULCAN MIND
IS FAR MORE DISCIPLINED
THAN YOURS.
IT CAN RESIST TEMPTATIONS,
EMOTIONS,
AND, I BELIEVE,
INVASIONS BY THESE LIFE-FORMS.
ARCHER: EVEN IF YOU'RE RIGHT,
WHAT WOULD YOU ACCOMPLISH?
T'POL: IF AN ALIEN ATTEMPTS
THIS TRANSFER,
THERE MAY BE A BRIEF PERIOD WHEN
OUR MINDS ARE CONJOINED.
IT'S POSSIBLE I COULD
ASCERTAIN THEIR MOTIVES.
ARCHER: IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
I WON'T LET YOU DO IT.
T'POL: THERE'S NO OTHER CHOICE.
ARCHER: AND IF YOU'RE WRONG?
T'POL: IT'S A RISK
I'M WILLING TO TAKE.
ARCHER: WELL, I'M NOT.
THEY'VE ALREADY TAKEN 24 PEOPLE.
I'M NOT GONNA GIVE THEM
ANOTHER ONE.
T'POL: YOU'VE TOLD ME
YOU TRUST MY JUDGMENT.
TRUST IT NOW UNLESS YOU
HAVE ANOTHER SUGGESTION.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
PHLOX: SICK BAY.
HOSHI: There's been an accident.
PHLOX: HOSHI?
HOSHI:
Hoshi Sato's been injured.
I don't know how to repair
the damage to her body.
PHLOX: WHAT HAPPENED?
HOSHI: Her leg is fractured.
She's in considerable pain.
She needs assistance.
PHLOX: I'M ARMED.
IF YOU'RE NEAR THE DOOR,
STEP AWAY.
HOSHI: She's on the floor.
She can't move.
PHLOX: THERE'S NOTHING
THE MATTER WITH YOU.
HOSHI: I NEED TO FIND
THE REST OF YOUR CREW.
WHERE ARE THEY?!
OHH. I'M GLAD I BROUGHT
YOU ALONG.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
DR. PHLOX.
ARCHER: Is everything going
all right, doc?
PHLOX: MORE OR LESS.
ARCHER: Good. T'Pol and I
are going to need your help.
PHLOX: SUB-COMMANDER?
T'POL?
HAVE YOU SUCCEEDED?
[SIGHS]
PHLOX TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: DID YOU FIND HER?
PHLOX: I'm with her now.
SHE'S NOT ACTING
LIKE THE OTHERS,
BUT SHE'S CERTAINLY
NOT HERSELF.
ARCHER: DOESN'T SOUND LIKE
THAT'S THE OUTCOME SHE EXPECTED.
PHLOX: Her neural pathways
are hyperstimulated.
ARCHER: DAMN IT.
YOU BETTER TAKE HER
TO HER QUARTERS.
PHLOX: Yes, Captain.
COME WITH ME.
EVERYTHING WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M AFRAID I HAVE TO INSIST.
I PROMISE YOU--
[T'POL BREATHING ERRATICALLY]
PHLOX: T'POL!
WHAT IS MY NAME?
SUB-COMMANDER!
T'POL: THEY'RE LYING TO US.
PHLOX: MY NAME.
T'POL: WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR THIS, PHLOX!
I HAVE TO GET
TO THE CAPTAIN.
THEIR SHIP IS DETERIORATING,
AND THEY HAVE NO WAY
TO REPAIR IT.
THEY CAN'T SURVIVE IN SPACE.
ARCHER: SO THEY ARE DOING THIS
TO SAVE THEMSELVES.
T'POL: 82 OF THEM ARE--
ONE FOR EVERY CREWMAN
ON "ENTERPRISE."
TRAVIS: HOW MANY OF THEM
ARE THERE?
T'POL: HUNDREDS.
THE REST WILL TRY TO
FIND ANOTHER VESSEL
OF CORPOREAL BEINGS.
WHERE'S COMMANDER TUCKER?
TRAVIS: I'M NOT SURE.
T'POL: PLEASE FIND HIM.
IF THE COMMANDER CAN FIND A WAY
TO SHIELD "ENTERPRISE,"
WE CAN LEAVE THE CATWALK
AND GO TO WARP.
ARCHER:
AND LOSE A THIRD OF THE CREW.
T'POL: 2/3 WILL SURVIVE.
ARCHER: UNACCEPTABLE.
WE'RE GOING TO FIND A WAY
TO GET THEM BACK.
T'POL: THAT MAY BE DIFFICULT.
ARCHER: CAN THEY SURVIVE
IN A HOST THAT'S DEAD?
T'POL: IT WOULD BE NO DIFFERENT
THAN BEING EXPOSED TO SPACE.
THEY'D DIE.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO PHLOX.
PHLOX: Yes, Captain.
TRAVIS: ARE YOU DOING ALL RIGHT?
CREWMAN: WE'RE OK.
SECOND CREWMAN: HOW LONG DO YOU
THINK WE'LL BE IN HERE, ENSIGN?
TRAVIS: I'M SURE THE CAPTAIN
WILL GET US OUT AS SOON
AS HE CAN.
HAS ANYONE SEEN
COMMANDER TUCKER?
FIRST CREWMAN: NO, SIR.
SECOND CREWMAN: NOT FOR A WHILE.
I THINK HE WAS DOWN THERE.
TRAVIS: THANKS.
PHLOX: WE'LL HAVE TO PURGE
THE CARBON DIOXIDE
WITHIN 20 SECONDS
OF RESPIRATORY FAILURE.
ARCHER: THAT'LL GIVE YOU
ENOUGH TIME TO RESUSCITATE THEM?
PHLOX:
OH, YES, IT'S ENOUGH TIME.
DON'T FORGET TO CLOSE OFF
THE VENTILATION
TO THE STARBOARD NACELLE.
We wouldn't want the gas to
affect you and the others.
ARCHER: UNDERSTOOD.
TRAVIS: SORRY, CAPTAIN,
I CAN'T FIND COMMANDER TUCKER.
ARCHER: HAS ANYONE OPENED EITHER
OF THE VENTRAL HATCHES?
T'POL: NOT SINCE WE SEALED THEM.
ARCHER: YOU MUST'VE MISSED HIM.
TRAVIS: I'LL LOOK AGAIN.
PHLOX: FOUR...
FIVE...
SIX...
SEVEN.
ARCHER: All right.
Does it have an I.D. tag?
PHLOX: JUNCTION 4-1-ALPHA,
ATMOSPHERIC RECYCLING MANIFOLD.
ARCHER: GOOD.
DO YOU SEE THE RELEASES
ON EITHER SIDE?
PHLOX: Yes.
There are, uh, four of them--
two blue,
TWO SILVER.
ARCHER: OPEN THEM,
THE SILVER ONES FIRST.
PHLOX: DONE.
ARCHER: Now pull the panel off.
PHLOX: WHAT SHOULD I DO WITH IT?
ARCHER: WHATEVER YOU WANT.
Lay it down on the floor.
PHLOX: VERY WELL.
AH! RIGHT WHERE YOU SAID
IT WAS, CAPTAIN. HA HA!
ARCHER: FIND THE CONTROL PANEL.
PHLOX: IT'S RIGHT HERE.
IT HAS SIX GREEN LIGHTS.
ARCHER: EACH OF THEM
SHOULD HAVE A SWITCH NEXT TO IT.
PHLOX: About
five centimeters to the left.
ARCHER: NOW, BEFORE
WE CAN RELEASE THE GAS
INTO CENTRAL VENTILATION,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO REROUTE THE TRANSFER LINES
TO THE CARBON-DIOXIDE TANKS.
PHLOX: AND HOW DO I GO ABOUT
DOING THAT?
T'POL: THOSE SIX SWITCHES
CONTROL THE FEED.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO RECALIBRATE THEM
IN SEQUENCE FOR CO2.
I'll guide you through it.
TRAVIS: COMMANDER, I'VE BEEN
LOOKING ALL OVER FOR YOU!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, SIR?
TUCKER: I'M FINE.
TRAVIS: THE CAPTAIN ASKED ME
TO FIND YOU.
HE NEEDS YOU
IN THE COMMAND COMPARTMENT.
COMMANDER?
[EXCITED CHATTER]
CREWMAN: ENSIGN, YOU ALL RIGHT?
TRAVIS:
YOU CAN'T GO OUT THERE, SIR.
IT'S NOT SAFE! UGH!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
PHLOX: I'VE REACHED
THE ACCESS TUBE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER:
Good. Now pull off the panel.
PHLOX: IT'S NOT COMING OFF.
ARCHER: IT'LL COME OFF.
YOU JUST NEED
TO USE A LITTLE MUSCLE.
PHLOX: I'VE USED EVERY
MUSCLE I'VE GOT. IT WON'T BUDGE.
ARCHER: TRY USING YOUR FOOT
FOR LEVERAGE.
PHLOX: GOOD SUGGESTION.
ARCHER: OK. NOW, THE NEXT PART'S
A PIECE OF CAKE.
TRAVIS:
WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: STAND BY, DOC.
WHAT HAPPENED?
TRAVIS: COMMANDER TUCKER--
HE JUST WENT OUT
THE FORWARD HATCH.
ARCHER: WHAT?!
TRAVIS:
I TRIED TO STOP HIM, SIR.
HE DIDN'T LOOK LIKE HIMSELF.
I THINK ONE OF THOSE THINGS
GOT INSIDE HIM.
T'POL: IF HE KNOWS
WHAT WE'RE DOING...
ARCHER: WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO SPEED THINGS UP, DOC.
TRIP'S BEEN TAKEN.
HE LEFT THE CATWALK
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
If he tries to let his buddies
out of their quarters,
we don't have any guards
down there to stop him.
PHLOX: TELL ME WHAT TO DO.
ARCHER: YOU'LL HAVE TO PURGE
THE OSMOTIC FILTERS.
The valves are right behind
the control circuit.
You're going to have
to get two fingers
through the upper holes
in the support plate.
NORMALLY, THAT WOULDN'T
BE A PROBLEM,
BUT WEARING THOSE GLOVES
COULD MAKE IT DIFFICULT.
PHLOX: BACK HOME, I'M KNOWN
FOR MY FINE MOTOR SKILLS.
I DOUBT A PAIR OF E.V. GLOVES
WILL DETER ME.
T'POL: THERE ARE TWO SOLENOIDS
BEHIND THE OPENINGS.
WHEN YOU TAP THEM
SIMULTANEOUSLY,
THE PLATE SHOULD RETRACT.
PHLOX: DID YOU SAY
THERE WERE TWO?
ARCHER:
ABOUT THREE CENTIMETERS APART.
PHLOX: GOT IT.
ARCHER: You should be looking at
2 rotary valves and a lever.
PHLOX: I SEE THEM.
ARCHER:
Open both valves all the way.
Then turn the lever
to the 3:00 position.
That should do it.
T'POL: The 9:00 position
will vent the gas
when we're finished.
[TUCKER COUGHING]
PHLOX: PHLOX TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: Go ahead.
PHLOX: MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.
I'm monitoring Commander Tucker.
ARCHER: GOOD JOB.
[REED GASPING]
PHLOX: IT'S LEFT
COMMANDER TUCKER.
ARCHER: Vent the gas.
PHLOX: IN A MOMENT, CAPTAIN.
I NEED TO BE CERTAIN
THE CO2 LEVEL IS CONSISTENT
THROUGHOUT THE SHIP,
THAT ALL THE LIFE-FORMS
ARE GONE.
ARCHER: READY, TRAVIS?
TRAVIS: YES, SIR.
PHLOX: IT'S DONE.
ARCHER: FULL IMPULSE!
T'POL: THEY'RE IN PURSUIT.
STAND BY.
NOW!
TUCKER: WHAT'S GOING ON, DOC?
PHLOX: JUST BREATHE DEEPLY.
YOU'LL BE FINE.
TUCKER: I WAS JUST
AT A BARBECUE.
PHLOX: IN THROUGH THE NOSE,
OUT THROUGH THE MOUTH.
TUCKER: I'VE NEVER
SEEN SO MANY RIBS!
PHLOX: FOLLOW ME, COMMANDER.
WE HAVE A LOT OF DOORS
TO UNLOCK.