[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
MAGISTRATE:
BRING IN THE PRISONER.
[SPECTATORS CHANTING "JAGH"]
YOU STAND ACCUSED OF CONSPIRING
AGAINST THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND?
ARCHER: I'M NOT GUILTY.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
MAGISTRATE: WHEN THIS TRIBUNAL
CONVENES TOMORROW,
YOU WILL BE GIVEN A CHANCE
TO PROVE YOUR INNOCENCE.
IF YOU CANNOT,
THERE IS ONLY ONE PUNISHMENT.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[SPECTATORS CHANTING "JAGH"]
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA
BEND OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
GUARD: YOU HAVE FIVE MINUTES.
ARCHER: GLAD YOU COULD DROP BY.
PHLOX: HOW ARE YOU?
ARCHER: I'VE BEEN BETTER.
PHLOX: I WASN'T SURE
IF I'D FIND YOU ALIVE.
ARCHER: THEY PROMISED ME A TRIAL
BEFORE THE EXECUTION.
SOMETHING WRONG?
PHLOX: XENOPOLYCYTHEMIA
CAN BE HIGHLY CONTAGIOUS.
I'M SURPRISED THEY
HAVEN'T PUT YOU IN ISOLATION.
ANY RESIDUAL SYMPTOMS?
FEVER, DIZZINESS?
ARCHER: JUST A SCRATCHY THROAT.
PHLOX: LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
ARCHER: WHEN DID YOU GET HERE?
PHLOX: TWO DAYS AGO,
BUT THEY REFUSED
TO LET US SEE YOU.
ARCHER: ENEMIES OF THE STATE
AREN'T ALLOWED VISITORS.
PHLOX: HMM. T'POL WAS
FINALLY ABLE TO CONVINCE THEM
THAT YOUR CONDITION
NECESSITATED A VISIT
FROM YOUR DOCTOR.
ARCHER: VERY THOUGHTFUL OF HER.
PHLOX: SHE SENDS HER REGARDS.
AND SHE WANTED ME TO
ASSURE YOU THAT STARFLEET
AND THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
ARE DOING EVERYTHING POSSIBLE
TO GET YOU RELEASED.
ARCHER:
AREN'T THEY HAVING ANY LUCK?
PHLOX: NOT YET.
BUT SHE AND COMMANDER TUCKER
HAVE BEGUN EXPLORING
OTHER OPTIONS
FOR REGAINING YOUR FREEDOM.
ARCHER: WHEN THIS IS OVER--
WHATEVER THE OUTCOME--
I'M COUNTING ON THEM
TO GET "ENTERPRISE" SAFELY
OUT OF KLINGON TERRITORY.
PHLOX: I'LL LET THEM KNOW.
HOW ARE YOUR ACCOMMODATIONS?
ARCHER: NOT SO BAD.
CAN'T SAY I'M A BIG FAN
OF KLINGON CUISINE.
PHLOX:
IT MAY NOT APPEAR APPETIZING,
BUT IT, UH, SEEMS LIKE
A GOOD SOURCE OF PROTEIN.
I SUGGEST YOU EAT IT.
KOLOS: IS HE INFECTIOUS?
PHLOX: I DON'T BELIEVE SO.
KOLOS: THEN RETURN TO YOUR SHIP.
PHLOX: I'D LIKE TO RUN
SOME MORE TESTS.
KOLOS:
YOU'RE NOT HERE TO TREAT HIM.
ARCHER:
THANKS FOR THE HOUSE CALL, DOC.
PHLOX: I'M SURE
I'LL SEE YOU SOON.
KOLOS: I'M KOLOS, YOUR ADVOCATE.
ARCHER: JONATHAN ARCHER.
KOLOS: HMM.
THE TRIBUNAL'S ABOUT TO BEGIN.
ARCHER: WE HAVEN'T EVEN
DISCUSSED WHAT HAPPENED.
KOLOS: I'M FAMILIAR
WITH THE CHARGES.
ARCHER: WELL, I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH YOUR JUSTICE SYSTEM.
WHAT CAN I EXPECT OUT THERE?
KOLOS: NOW THAT
YOU'VE BEEN CHARGED,
THE EVIDENCE AGAINST YOU
WILL BE PRESENTED.
ARCHER: WHEN DO I GET A CHANCE
TO TESTIFY?
KOLOS:
I WILL CONDUCT YOUR DEFENSE.
ARCHER: HOW CAN YOU DO THAT
WHEN YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED?
KOLOS: I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU MUSTN'T
SPEAK DURING THE TRIBUNAL.
I'LL SPEAK FOR YOU.
[CROWD CHANTING "JAGH"]
ARCHER: WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
KOLOS: "ENEMY."
ARCHER:
I HOPE THEY'RE NOT THE JURY.
KOLOS: THERE IS NO JURY.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
ARCHER: WHO'S THAT?
KOLOS: PROSECUTOR ORAK.
HIS SUCCESS IS WELL KNOWN.
ARCHER: WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WHAT'S YOUR SUCCESS RATE?
KOLOS: I PERFORM MY DUTY.
[LOUD SHOUTS]
MAGISTRATE:
THIS TRIBUNAL IS CONVENED.
STRENGTH TO THE EMPIRE!
PROSECUTOR ORAK,
YOU MAY PROCEED.
ORAK:
I CALL DURAS, SON OF TORAL.
CAPTAIN DURAS,
TELL THE TRIBUNAL
ABOUT YOUR ENCOUNTER
WITH THE ACCUSED.
DURAS: I AM NO LONGER A CAPTAIN.
ORAK: EXPLAIN.
DURAS:
I AM A SECOND WEAPONS OFFICER
SERVING ON THE TY'GOKOR
DEFENSE PERIMETER.
ORAK:
THE DURAS I CALLED TO TESTIFY
IS COMMANDER
OF THE BATTLE CRUISER "BORTAS."
DURAS:
I WAS RECENTLY REDUCED IN RANK.
ORAK:
A DISTINGUISHED KLINGON WARRIOR
STRIPPED OF HIS COMMAND.
DID THE ACCUSED HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH YOUR DISGRACE?
DURAS: YES.
ORAK:
GO ON, WEAPONS OFFICER DURAS.
DURAS:
A GROUP OF REBELS HAD FLED
THE KLINGON PROTECTORATE
AT RAATOORAS.
I WAS COMMANDED TO BRING
THESE TRAITORS TO JUSTICE.
WE'D FOLLOWED THEIR WARP TRAIL
TO A SYSTEM JUST OUTSIDE
KLINGON TERRITORY.
OFFICER:
THEY'RE NEAR THE FIFTH PLANET.
ANOTHER VESSEL
IS DOCKED WITH THEM.
DURAS: SHOW ME.
WHAT KIND OF SHIP IS THAT?
OFFICER: UNKNOWN.
BUT THEY'VE
TAKEN THE REBELS ABOARD.
DURAS: ARMAMENTS?
OFFICER: TORPEDO LAUNCHERS
FORE AND AFT.
LOW-YIELD PARTICLE CANNONS.
WE CAN DEFEAT THEM EASILY.
DURAS: INTERCEPT.
OFFICER: THEY'RE SIGNALING US.
DURAS: VIEWER.
IDENTIFY YOURSELF.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN ARCHER OF
THE BATTLE CRUISER ENTERPRISE.
DURAS: THE PEOPLE ABOARD YOUR
SHIP ARE WANTED FOR TREASON.
SURRENDER THEM IMMEDIATELY.
ARCHER: BY WHOSE AUTHORITY?
DURAS: THE CHANCELLOR
OF THE KLINGON HIGH COUNCIL.
ARCHER:
I DON'T KNOW YOUR CHANCELLOR,
AND I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
WHAT HE WANTS.
I'VE FORMED AN ALLIANCE
WITH THESE PEOPLE,
AND I'M GOING TO SUPPORT
THEIR REVOLT.
DURAS: GIVE THEM TO ME NOW
OR I'LL DESTROY YOUR VESSEL.
ARCHER: FIRE ONE SHOT,
AND YOU'LL BE JOINING YOUR
ANCESTORS IN THE AFTERLIFE.
ORAK: HE REFUSED
TO SURRENDER THE REBELS?
DURAS: YES.
ARCHER: I DIDN'T SAY
ANY OF THOSE THINGS.
CAN'T YOU OBJECT?
KOLOS: IT'S NOT IMPORTANT.
ORAK: AND HOW DID YOU
RESPOND TO ARCHER'S DEFIANCE?
DURAS: I PITIED HIM.
HE WAS ABOUT TO DIE IN DEFENSE
OF THESE WRETCHED TRAITORS.
ARCHER: THEY WEREN'T TRAITORS.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
MAGISTRATE: ADVOCATE, HAVEN'T
YOU INFORMED THE PRISONER
OF THE RULES OF THIS TRIBUNAL?
KOLOS: MY APOLOGIES, MAGISTRATE.
BE SILENT
OR YOU WILL BE REMOVED.
ORAK: CONTINUE.
DURAS: I SHOWED HIM
MORE PATIENCE THAN HE DESERVED.
BUT OBVIOUSLY
HE WANTED BLOOD TO BE SPILLED.
DON'T BE A FOOL.
YOUR SHIP IS INFERIOR.
YOU WON'T SURVIVE
A BATTLE WITH US.
ARCHER: DEATH TO THE EMPIRE.
DURAS: RETURN FIRE!
OFFICER: THEY'RE HEADING
FOR THE RING SYSTEM.
DURAS:
THE COWARD THINKS HE CAN HIDE.
PURSUE THEM!
WHERE ARE THEY?
ANSWER ME!
OFFICER: DEBRIS IS INTERFERING
WITH SENSORS.
DURAS: THERE! TARGET
THEIR ENGINES! ALL WEAPONS!
OFFICER: WE'VE LOST SENSORS.
SHIELDS ARE DOWN!
DURAS: MANUAL TARGETING! FIRE!
OFFICER: THEY'RE LEAVING ORBIT!
DURAS: FOLLOW THEM!
OFFICER: OUR ENGINES ARE DOWN.
[DURAS YELLS]
DURAS: IT TOOK US 3 HOURS
TO REPAIR OUR WARP DRIVE.
ORAK: BUT, OF COURSE,
BY THAT TIME, THEY WERE GONE.
YOU'RE FORTUNATE
YOUR FIRST OFFICER
DIDN'T KILL YOU
FOR SUCH A FAILURE.
YOU'RE DISMISSED.
ARCHER: YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO QUESTION HIM?
KOLOS: HE'D SAY NOTHING
THAT WOULD HELP YOU.
MAGISTRATE: DO YOU HAVE
ANY FURTHER EVIDENCE TO PRESENT?
ORAK: NO, MAGISTRATE.
DURAS' TESTIMONY IS CLEAR.
HE WAS ATTEMPTING
TO CARRY OUT HIS MISSION--
TO BRING ENEMIES
OF THE EMPIRE TO JUSTICE.
BUT THIS AGGRESSOR,
THIS HUMAN,
CONSPIRED WITH THEM
TO DISGRACE A PROUD WARRIOR
AND FOMENT REBELLION.
THERE CAN BE NO DOUBT
THAT HE IS OUR ENEMY AS WELL.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
CAPTAIN ARCHER CLAIMS
TO BE INNOCENT!
INNOCENT OF WHAT?
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
THIS TRIBUNAL HAS ALREADY
BEEN FAR TOO LENIENT.
WE HAVEN'T ACCUSED HIS CREW
OR HIS GOVERNMENT.
HE'S FORTUNATE
WE HAVEN'T DISPATCHED
A FLEET OF WARSHIPS
TO HIS HOMEWORLD!
BUT WE DO DEMAND
THAT HE BE HELD RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE CRIMES HE HAS COMMITTED.
WE DEMAND THAT HE RECEIVE
THE MOST SEVERE PUNISHMENT
OUR LAWS DECREE!
JAGH!
[SPECTATORS CHANTING "JAGH"]
MAGISTRATE:
DO YOU HAVE A RESPONSE?
KOLOS: NO, MAGISTRATE.
MAGISTRATE: THEN
I WILL CONSIDER THE EVIDENCE
AND DELIVER MY VERDICT--
ARCHER: I'D LIKE A CHANCE
TO DEFEND MYSELF.
MAGISTRATE:
YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED.
ARCHER:
HE'S DISTORTING THE TRUTH!
MAGISTRATE: BE SILENT!
ARCHER:
THOSE PEOPLE WEREN'T REBELS.
AND I WASN'T TRYING
TO START A REBELLION.
I AM NOT YOUR ENEMY!
UGH!
[MAGISTRATE POUNDS GAVEL]
MAGISTRATE:
THIS TRIBUNAL IS IN RECESS.
ARCHER: WHAT IS THIS?
KOLOS: TARG.
ARCHER: IT'S A LITTLE UNDERDONE.
KOLOS:
I TOLD YOU TO REMAIN SILENT.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
LISTENED TO ME.
ARCHER: SORRY IF I INTERFERED
WITH YOUR LEGAL STRATEGY.
KOLOS: MY STRATEGY
MAY YET SPARE YOUR LIFE.
I'VE SPOKEN
WITH THE MAGISTRATE.
HE'S WILLING TO SHOW YOU
MERCY IF YOU COOPERATE.
ARCHER: HOW?
KOLOS: TELL HIM
WHERE TO FIND THE REBELS.
ARCHER: I TOLD YOU,
THEY'RE NOT REBELS.
KOLOS: IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT YOU BELIEVE.
THEY'RE SUBJECT TO THE LAWS
OF THE EMPIRE.
THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN SAY
THAT WILL CHANGE THAT.
ARCHER: I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO SAY ANYTHING.
KOLOS: WHERE DID YOU TAKE THEM?
ANOTHER SHIP?
A PLANET?
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IF YOU DON'T TELL THEM?
ARCHER:
I HAVE A PRETTY GOOD IDEA.
KOLOS: I'M OFFERING YOU
A WAY TO SAVE YOUR LIFE.
ARCHER:
LET'S SAY I DID COOPERATE.
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO THESE PEOPLE?
KOLOS: THEY WOULD BE CHARGED
WITH TREASON.
ARCHER: AND END UP IN A COURT
LIKE THIS ONE?
TELL THE MAGISTRATE
I'M GONNA PASS ON HIS OFFER.
KOLOS: ONLY A FOOL WOULD
SACRIFICE HIMSELF
FOR PEOPLE HE BARELY KNOWS.
ARCHER: I KNOW THEM WELL ENOUGH.
THEY'RE GOOD PEOPLE.
AND I WON'T TURN THEM OVER.
IF YOU'D LET ME TESTIFY,
TELL MY SIDE OF THE STORY,
IT MIGHT BECOME CLEAR
WHY I HELPED THEM.
BUT FROM WHAT I'VE SEEN,
YOU'RE ALL PERFECTLY HAPPY
TO IGNORE WHAT YOU
DON'T WANT TO HEAR.
KOLOS: DON'T BE SO QUICK
TO ACCUSE ME OF SHARING
THEIR INTERPRETATION
OF THE LAW.
ARCHER: NO?
WHAT'S YOUR INTERPRETATION?
KOLOS: I BECAME AN ADVOCATE
MANY YEARS AGO.
THEY WERE DIFFERENT TIMES.
ARCHER: BETTER OR WORSE?
KOLOS: THE COURTS WERE
MORE WILLING TO LISTEN.
ARCHER: THEN MAYBE
YOU SHOULD REMIND THEM
OF THOSE DIFFERENT TIMES.
NOTHING LIKE
A GOOD HISTORY LESSON.
[KOLOS SIGHS]
KOLOS: I'M AN OLD MAN--
TOO OLD TO CHALLENGE THE RULES.
ARCHER: EVEN IF YOUR CLIENT'S
LIFE DEPENDS ON IT?
I GET THE FEELING YOU'RE
AS FRUSTRATED AS I AM,
THAT YOU WANT TO
STAND UP TO THEM.
BUT YOU'VE GIVEN UP.
YOU'RE AFRAID OF THEM.
KOLOS: I'M NOT AFRAID.
ARCHER:
THEN PROVE IT. CHALLENGE THEM.
SHOW THEM WHAT
A REAL TRIAL IS LIKE.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS
IN KLINGON]
MAGISTRATE:
STRENGTH TO THE EMPIRE.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
MAGISTRATE: HAVE YOU INFORMED
THE ACCUSED OF OUR OFFER?
KOLOS: I HAVE.
MAGISTRATE: AND DOES HE
WISH TO ADDRESS THIS TRIBUNAL?
KOLOS: HE DOES.
HE WISHES TO TESTIFY
IN HIS OWN DEFENSE.
ORAK: I OBJECT!
THE TIME FOR TESTIMONY IS OVER.
KOLOS: WITH RESPECT TO
MAGISTRATE,
NO VERDICT HAS BEEN REACHED.
ORAK: IRRELEVANT! I URGE YOU
TO END THESE PROCEEDINGS.
KOLOS: I'M WITHIN MY RIGHTS
TO PRESENT FURTHER TESTIMONY.
ORAK: YOU'RE SPEAKING
OF ARCHAIC RIGHTS.
KOLOS: SURELY I DON'T NEED
TO REMIND THE MAGISTRATE
THE JUDICIAL CHARTER
OF KOLOTH STATES
AN ADVOCATE IS ENTITLED
TO CHALLENGE THE CHARGES
AT ANY POINT
DURING THE TRIBUNAL.
TO MY KNOWLEDGE,
THAT CHARTER HAS NOT
BEEN CAST ASIDE.
FROM THE TIME OF KAHLESS,
OUR COURTS HAVE STOOD AS A FORUM
WHERE JUSTICE
IS DISPENSED WITH HONOR!
[SPECTATORS MURMURING]
NOW, WILL MY CASE
BE HEARD OR WILL IT NOT?
MAGISTRATE: CALL YOUR WITNESS.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
KOLOS: IDENTIFY YOURSELF.
ARCHER:
I'M CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER
OF THE EARTH STARSHIP
"ENTERPRISE."
ORAK:
DO YOU ADMIT, CAPTAIN ARCHER,
THAT YOU GAVE AID AND COMFORT
TO A VESSEL FLEEING THE EMPIRE?
ARCHER:
WE ANSWERED A DISTRESS CALL.
THEY WERE STARVING.
THEIR LIFE SUPPORT WAS FAILING.
ORAK: THEIR HEALTH
ISN'T AT ISSUE HERE.
YOU HELPED THEM TO ESCAPE!
KOLOS: WILL MY CLIENT
BE ALLOWED TO TESTIFY OR NOT?
MAGISTRATE: PROSECUTOR,
YOU WILL SHOW THE ADVOCATE
THE SAME RESPECT
HE HAS SHOWN YOU.
CONTINUE.
KOLOS:
RECOUNT FOR THIS TRIBUNAL
YOUR RECOLLECTION OF THE EVENTS.
ARCHER: AS I SAID,
WE HAD RECEIVED A DISTRESS CALL.
MAGNIFY.
BIO-SIGNS?
T'POL: 27.
ARCHER: ANY RESPONSE?
HOSHI: NO, SIR.
ARCHER: MALCOLM?
REED: MAIN PROPULSION'S OFFLINE.
LIFE SUPPORT IS FAILING.
THEY'RE IN A BAD WAY, SIR.
ARCHER:
CAN YOU DOCK WITH THEM?
TRAVIS: THEIR PORT ENGINE
IS VENTING REACTOR COOLANT.
I COULD TRY TO COME IN
ON THE STARBOARD SIDE,
BUT IT'LL BE TRICKY.
ARCHER: DO YOUR BEST.
PATIENT: OUR WARP DRIVE FAILED
THREE WEEKS AFTER WE LEFT.
WE TRIED TO SET A COURSE
FOR THE NEAREST SYSTEM
AT IMPULSE,
BUT MAIN POWER WENT DOWN.
ARCHER: HOW LONG AGO WAS THAT?
PATIENT: I DON'T KNOW.
SIX WEEKS. MAYBE MORE.
WE DIVERTED AUXILIARY POWER
TO LIFE SUPPORT,
BUT IT WASN'T ENOUGH.
FOOD PROCESSORS FAILED,
WATER RECYCLERS.
PHLOX: I'VE PUT THEM ALL ON
PROTEIN SUPPLEMENTS,
BUT TWO OF THEM ARE
IN SERIOUS CONDITION.
PATIENT: WHEN WE LEFT,
THERE WERE 54 ABOARD.
ARCHER:
WHAT BROUGHT YOU OUT HERE?
PATIENT: SEVERAL YEARS AGO,
OUR COLONY WAS ANNEXED
BY A SPECIES
WE HAD NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
THEY SAID THEY'D PROVIDE FOR US
IN EXCHANGE FOR OUR ALLEGIANCE,
THAT WE'D BECOME
A PART OF THEIR EMPIRE.
BUT THEY STRIPPED US
OF OUR RESOURCES,
LEFT US WITH NOTHING.
WE WAITED FOR THEM TO RETURN.
THEY SAID
THEY'D BRING FOOD, FUEL.
THEY NEVER CAME BACK.
KOLOS: YOU KNEW
THEY WERE FLEEING THE EMPIRE.
ARCHER: WE KNEW THAT
THEIR COLONY HAD BEEN ABANDONED.
KOLOS: AND YOU CHOSE
TO SHOW THEM COMPASSION.
ARCHER: THEY WERE STARVING.
THEY WOULDN'T
HAVE LASTED ANOTHER WEEK.
ORAK: THEY WERE
SUBJECTS OF THE EMPIRE.
THEIR WELFARE
WAS NOT YOUR CONCERN.
ARCHER: APPARENTLY
IT WASN'T YOURS, EITHER.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
ORAK: YOU SEE THE CONTEMPT
THESE HUMANS HAVE FOR US.
HE STILL BELIEVES
HE DID NOTHING WRONG.
KOLOS: AND PROSECUTOR ORAK
HAS YET TO PROVE THAT HE HAS.
ORAK: HE AIDED THESE REBELS.
AND NOW HE REFUSES TO HELP US
BRING THEM TO JUSTICE!
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
MAGISTRATE: I WILL HEAR
WHAT THE ACCUSED HAS TO SAY.
KOLOS: CONTINUE.
ARCHER:
MY CHIEF ENGINEER HAD DETERMINED
THAT THEIR VESSEL
WAS BEYOND REPAIR.
SOME OF THE CREW
WILL HAVE TO DOUBLE UP,
BUT I THINK WE CAN
ACCOMMODATE ALL OF THEM.
T'POL: I'VE ALREADY
GIVEN THE ORDER.
CONSIDERING THE ALTERNATIVE
WAS TO SET THE SHIP ADRIFT,
I ANTICIPATED YOUR DECISION.
WHERE DO YOU PLAN TO TAKE THEM?
ARCHER:
THEY WERE HEADED FOR A SYSTEM
A FEW LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE.
THAT SHOULD KEEP THEM SAFE
FROM THE KLINGONS.
T'POL: EMPIRES TEND TO EXPAND.
THEY MAY EVENTUALLY DISCOVER
THEY HAVEN'T TRAVELED
FAR ENOUGH.
REED: Captain, please report
to the bridge.
ARCHER:
LOOKS LIKE THEY DIDN'T ABANDON
THE COLONISTS AFTER ALL.
REED: PERHAPS THEY'RE BRINGING
THE SUPPLIES THEY PROMISED.
T'POL: IT'S A D5 BATTLE CRUISER.
I DOUBT IT'S BRINGING SUPPLIES.
ARCHER:
HOW LONG BEFORE THEY GET HERE?
REED: 17 MINUTES.
ARCHER:
ARE ALL THE REFUGEES ABOARD?
REED: YES, SIR.
ARCHER: CUT THEIR SHIP LOOSE
AND GO TO TACTICAL ALERT.
ORAK: SO YOU WERE PREPARING
FOR BATTLE.
ARCHER: I WAS PREPARING
TO DEFEND MY SHIP.
KOLOS: AS ANY GOOD KLINGON
COMMANDER WOULD BE.
ORAK:
THE ACCUSED HAS ALREADY ADMITTED
THAT HE KNEW THE REBELS
WERE SUBJECTS OF THE EMPIRE.
ARCHER: THEY MAY HAVE BEEN
SUBJECTS OF THE EMPIRE,
BUT IT SURE AS HELL LOOKED
LIKE YOU HAD ABANDONED THEM.
ORAK: AND HE KNEW THE "BORTAS"
WAS COMING TO RETRIEVE THEM,
YET HE LAUNCHED
A DELIBERATE ATTACK
AGAINST AN IMPERIAL VESSEL!
THIS HUMAN IS GUILTY
OF MORE THAN INCITING REBELLION.
HE HAS COMMITTED AN ACT OF WAR!
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
REED: I DON'T SUPPOSE THERE'S
ANY CHANCE OF OUTRUNNING THEM.
T'POL:
THEIR MAXIMUM SPEED IS WARP 6.
TRAVIS: IF WE COULD DISABLE
THEIR ENGINES...
REED: SUSTAINED FIRE
FROM OUR PHASE CANNONS
SHOULD BE ABLE TO PENETRATE
THEIR ARMOR,
BUT I DOUBT THEY'D SIT STILL
LONG ENOUGH
TO GIVE US THE CHANCE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE COMPOSITION
OF THOSE RINGS?
T'POL: NOTHING UNUSUAL.
METHANE ICE, ISOLYTIC PLASMA,
DIAMAGNETIC DUST.
ARCHER: WHEN WE PULLED
THAT KLINGON SHIP
OUT OF THE GAS GIANT,
DID YOU GET A LOOK
AT THEIR SENSOR ARRAY?
REED: PRETTY STANDARD
MULTISPECTRAL SENSORS,
NOT TOO DIFFERENT FROM OURS.
ARCHER: IF WE COULD IGNITE
THE PLASMA IN THOSE RINGS,
WOULD IT DISRUPT THEIR SENSORS?
REED: FOR A FEW SECONDS.
ARCHER:
A FEW SECONDS WILL HAVE TO DO.
CAN YOU MODIFY A TORPEDO?
REED: I BELIEVE SO.
ARCHER: HOW LONG?
REED: HOW LONG DO I HAVE?
T'POL: THE KLINGON SHIP WILL BE
HERE IN LESS THAN 11 MINUTES.
ARCHER: GET MOVING.
ORAK: SO YOU LAID A TRAP
FOR THE "BORTAS."
ARCHER: WE HAD NO INTENTION
OF FIRING FIRST.
ORAK: OH, SUCH A NOBLE HUMAN.
KOLOS: I WAS ASSURED THE ACCUSED
WOULD BE ALLOWED TO SPEAK
WITHOUT INTERRUPTION.
ORAK: BY ALL MEANS.
I FIND HIS VERSION OF EVENTS
EXTREMELY ENTERTAINING.
[LAUGHTER]
ARCHER: THE "BORTAS" HAD DROPPED
OUT OF WARP
WITH THEIR WEAPONS CHARGED.
TRAVIS:
THEY'RE ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
200,000 KILOMETERS AND CLOSING.
ARCHER: HAIL THEM.
DURAS: IDENTIFY YOURSELF.
ARCHER: I'M JONATHAN ARCHER,
CAPTAIN
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
DURAS: YOU'RE HARBORING
FUGITIVES. SURRENDER THEM.
ARCHER: I WASN'T AWARE
THEY'D COMMITTED ANY CRIME.
DURAS: THEY'RE WANTED
FOR INCITING REBELLION.
ARCHER: FROM WHAT I CAN TELL,
THEY ARE IN NO CONDITION
TO INCITE ANYTHING.
APPARENTLY THEIR COLONY
WAS ABANDONED BY YOUR--
DURAS: TURN OVER THE REBELS NOW!
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU INTEND
TO DO WITH THEM?
DURAS:
THAT'S NONE OF YOUR CONCERN.
ARCHER: I'M SORRY, BUT I'M
NOT PREPARED TO HAND THEM OVER
WITHOUT A LITTLE
MORE INFORMATION.
IF I COULD SPEAK TO SOMEONE
IN YOUR GOVERNMENT--
DURAS: I SPEAK FOR THE EMPIRE.
ARCHER: FAIR ENOUGH.
LET'S SIT DOWN AND TRY TO--
REED: HULL PLATING'S AT 80%.
NO DAMAGE TO THE KLINGON SHIP.
ARCHER: HEAD INTO THE RINGS.
T'POL:
THEY'RE PURSUING. 10,000 METERS.
T'POL: WE'RE APPROACHING A LARGE
FRAGMENT 600 METERS IN DIAMETER,
BEARING 227 MARK 4.
ARCHER: PUT US BEHIND IT.
REED: THEY'RE CLOSING, SIR.
4,000 METERS.
ARCHER: STAND BY.
REED: 3,000 METERS.
2,000.
800 METERS.
ARCHER: FIRE!
REED: OUR SENSORS ARE DOWN.
ARCHER:
LET'S HOPE THEIRS ARE, TOO.
GET US OUT OF HERE.
KOLOS: YOU SAY THE "BORTAS"
FIRED FIRST.
ARCHER: YES.
KOLOS: AND YOU TRIED TO REACH
AN ACCOMMODATION
WITH CAPTAIN DURAS?
ARCHER: HE REFUSED.
ORAK:
DURAS WAS UNDER NO OBLIGATION
TO ACCOMMODATE THIS HUMAN.
KOLOS: SO YOU WERE SIMPLY
DEFENDING YOUR SHIP
WHEN YOU ATTACKED THE "BORTAS"?
ARCHER: YES.
KOLOS: AND THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
ARCHER: WE LEFT THE SYSTEM
AND TOOK THE REFUGEES WITH US.
KOLOS: YOU COULD HAVE DESTROYED
THE "BORTAS."
WHY DIDN'T YOU?
ARCHER: BECAUSE CAPTAIN DURAS
IS NOT MY ENEMY.
KOLOS: NOT YOUR ENEMY?
I SUBMIT TO THIS TRIBUNAL
THAT CAPTAIN ARCHER IS GUILTY...
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
GUILTY OF MEDDLING
IN KLINGON AFFAIRS
ON MORE THAN ONE OCCASION.
IN FACT, I'VE DISCOVERED
HIS NAME IS WELL KNOWN
TO THE HIGH COUNCIL.
THE ACCUSED ONCE STOOD
BEFORE THE CHANCELLOR HIMSELF
AND EXPOSED A SULIBAN PLOT
THAT WOULD HAVE THROWN
THE EMPIRE INTO CIVIL WAR.
ORAK: THAT IS ABSURD.
KOLOS: THE FACTS ARE ON RECORD.
PERHAPS THE PROSECUTOR
HAS GROWN COMPLACENT
WITH HIS RESEARCH.
THE RECORDS
OF THE IMPERIAL FLEET
ALSO MENTION THIS MAN.
HIS SHIP WAS INSTRUMENTAL
IN THE RESCUE OF THE KLINGON
RAPTOR THE "SOMRAW"
FROM THE DENSE ATMOSPHERE
OF A GAS GIANT.
ORAK: EVEN IF THIS IS TRUE,
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS CASE!
KOLOS: IT HAS EVERYTHING
TO DO WITH THIS CASE.
IT SHOWS A PATTERN
IN ARCHER'S BEHAVIOR
THAT WAS REPEATED IN HIS
ENCOUNTER WITH CAPTAIN DURAS.
YES, HE MAY BE SELF-RIGHTEOUS,
BUT HIS MEDDLING
HAS SAVED A KLINGON SHIP
AND PERHAPS THE FATE
OF THE EMPIRE ITSELF.
IF CAPTAIN ARCHER IS GUILTY,
HE IS GUILTY OF NOTHING MORE
THAN BEING A NUISANCE
AND HARDLY WORTH
THE ATTENTION OF THIS TRIBUNAL.
AND IF HE MUST BE PUNISHED,
LET THE PUNISHMENT FIT
THAT CRIME.
ARCHER: HOW LONG SHOULD IT TAKE
FOR A VERDICT?
KOLOS: IT USUALLY DOESN'T
TAKE LONG AT ALL.
I MUST HAVE BEEN MORE
PERSUASIVE THAN I THOUGHT.
[KOLOS CHUCKLES]
ARCHER: THANKS FOR WHAT YOU'VE
DONE FOR ME.
KOLOS: OH, DON'T THANK ME YET.
THE ODDS ARE STILL
VERY MUCH AGAINST US.
ARCHER: WHAT IS IT?
KOLOS: BLOODWINE.
IT SHOULD HELP MAKE
THE WAIT MORE PLEASANT.
ARCHER: WHAT'S IT THE BLOOD OF?
[KOLOS CHUCKLES]
KOLOS: DON'T FEEL BADLY
IF YOU CAN'T STOMACH IT.
ARCHER: I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
HOW MANY CASES HAVE YOU WON?
KOLOS: OH, I'M NOT SURE.
OVER 200.
BUT THAT WAS A LONG TIME AGO,
WHEN THE TRIBUNAL
WAS A FORUM FOR THE TRUTH
AND NOT A TOOL
FOR THE WARRIOR CLASS.
ARCHER: THERE ARE OTHER CLASSES?
KOLOS: YOU DIDN'T BELIEVE
ALL KLINGONS WERE SOLDIERS?
ARCHER: I GUESS I DID.
KOLOS: AH.
MY FATHER WAS A TEACHER,
MY MOTHER A BIOLOGIST
AT THE UNIVERSITY.
THEY ENCOURAGED ME
TO TAKE UP THE LAW.
NOW ALL YOUNG PEOPLE
WANT TO DO IS TAKE UP WEAPONS
AS SOON AS THEY
CAN HOLD THEM.
THEY'RE TOLD THERE'S HONOR
IN VICTORY, ANY VICTORY.
BUT WHAT HONOR IS THERE
IN A VICTORY
OVER A WEAKER OPPONENT?
HAD DURAS DESTROYED THAT SHIP,
HE WOULD HAVE BEEN LAUDED
AS A HERO OF THE EMPIRE
FOR MURDERING HELPLESS REFUGEES.
[KOLOS SIGHS]
WE WERE A GREAT SOCIETY
NOT SO LONG AGO,
WHEN HONOR WAS EARNED
THROUGH INTEGRITY
AND ACTS OF TRUE COURAGE,
NOT SENSELESS BLOODSHED.
ARCHER: FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS,
MY PEOPLE HAD SIMILAR PROBLEMS.
WE FOUGHT THREE WORLD WARS
THAT ALMOST DESTROYED US.
WHOLE GENERATIONS
WERE NEARLY WIPED OUT.
KOLOS: WHAT CHANGED?
ARCHER: A FEW COURAGEOUS PEOPLE
BEGAN TO REALIZE
THEY COULD MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
[LOCK TURNS]
MAGISTRATE: I HAVE WEIGHED
THE EVIDENCE CAREFULLY.
ADVOCATE KOLOS HAS MADE
AN IMPRESSIVE CASE
MUCH TO THE SURPRISE
OF THIS TRIBUNAL.
BASED UPON HIS ARGUMENTS,
I AM INCLINED TO BELIEVE
THAT THE ACCUSED WAS A VICTIM
OF HIS OWN FOOLISHNESS.
HE WAS NOT FOMENTING REBELLION.
BUT, AS PROSECUTOR ORAK
HAS MADE CLEAR,
THE LAWS OF THE EMPIRE
HAVE BEEN VIOLATED.
AND CAPTAIN ARCHER
MUST BE HELD ACCOUNTABLE
FOR HIS ACTIONS
REGARDLESS OF HIS INTENT.
I THEREFORE FIND THE ACCUSED
GUILTY AS CHARGED.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
MAGISTRATE: HOWEVER...
HOWEVER...
THIS TRIBUNAL
CANNOT IGNORE HIS ACTIONS
ASSISTING THE KLINGON PEOPLE.
THEREFORE, THE SENTENCE OF DEATH
IS COMMUTED.
[KLINGONS GRUMBLING]
MAGISTRATE: SILENCE!
JONATHAN ARCHER,
YOU ARE CONDEMNED
TO THE DILITHIUM MINES
ON THE PENAL COLONY
OF RURA PENTHE
FOR THE REMAINDER OF YOUR LIFE.
MAGISTRATE: REMOVE THE PRISONER.
ORAK: I PROTEST.
MAGISTRATE: I WOULDN'T PROTEST
TOO LOUDLY, PROSECUTOR.
YOU'VE WON YOUR CASE.
ORAK: AND I COMPLIMENT
THE MAGISTRATE
ON HIS JUST RULING.
BUT THE SENTENCE
FOR THESE CRIMES MUST BE DEATH.
KOLOS: THE SENTENCE IS DEATH.
YOU CONDEMN THIS MAN
TO RURA PENTHE.
WHAT IS THE LIFE EXPECTANCY
OF A PRISONER THERE?
SIX MONTHS,
A YEAR AT THE MOST?
AND YOU EXPECT US TO BELIEVE
THAT THIS IS AN ACT OF MERCY.
MAGISTRATE:
THIS COURT HAS SHOWN YOU
A GREAT DEAL
OF PATIENCE, ADVOCATE.
DON'T TEST MY LIMITS
ANY FURTHER.
KOLOS: I ASK
FOR NO SPECIAL TREATMENT,
ONLY THAT MY CLIENT
BE JUDGED FAIRLY,
AS ANY KLINGON WOULD BE JUDGED.
BUT IT HAS BEEN MANY YEARS
SINCE ANYONE STOOD
IN THIS CHAMBER
AND RECEIVED JUSTICE.
MAGISTRATE: WATCH YOUR WORDS.
YOU INSULT THE HONOR
OF THIS TRIBUNAL.
KOLOS: HONOR?!
YOU ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT CAPTAIN ARCHER
ACTED WITH CONVICTION
AND INTEGRITY.
AND HOW DO YOU REWARD HIM?
WITH THIS GRAND PUBLIC
DISPLAY OF COMPASSION
BEFORE SENDING HIM TO HIS DEATH
IN A FROZEN CAVE!
MAGISTRATE: ENOUGH!
KOLOS: FORGIVE ME IF I FAIL
TO SEE THE HONOR IN THAT!
MAGISTRATE: YOU ARE IN CONTEMPT
OF THIS TRIBUNAL.
SINCE YOU HAVE SUCH ADMIRATION
FOR THE PRISONER,
YOU WILL JOIN HIM ON RURA PENTHE
FOR A PERIOD OF ONE YEAR.
[SPECTATORS SHOUTING]
REMOVE THEM BOTH.
T'POL: THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND
WILL CONTINUE TO LOBBY
FOR THE CAPTAIN'S RELEASE.
TUCKER: SO WHAT DO WE DO?
T'POL: THE KLINGONS HAVE
ONLY ALLOWED US TO REMAIN HERE
DURING THE TRIAL.
WE'RE TO LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
REED: AND ABANDON THE CAPTAIN?
T'POL: WE DON'T HAVE A CHOICE.
TRAVIS:
WHAT'S THIS RURA PENTHE LIKE?
T'POL: IT'S QUITE INHOSPITABLE.
REED: THEY'RE GONNA HAVE
TO GET THERE.
T'POL: WE'RE DEEP INSIDE
KLINGON TERRITORY.
A RESCUE ATTEMPT
IS OUT OF THE QUESTION.
TUCKER: I'M WILLING TO RISK IT.
T'POL: THE CAPTAIN ISN'T.
HE MADE IT CLEAR
HE DIDN'T WANT US
TO ENDANGER THE CREW
ON HIS BEHALF.
TUCKER: SO YOU'RE SAYING WE
JUST FORGET ABOUT HIM?
T'POL: I'M SAYING A RESCUE
ISN'T AN OPTION.
BUT THERE ARE
DIPLOMATIC CHANNELS.
TUCKER:
WE TRIED DIPLOMATIC CHANNELS.
T'POL: NOT ALL OF THEM.
I'VE DEALT WITH SEVERAL KLINGON
BUREAUCRATS IN THE PAST.
SOME OF THEM CAN BE PERSUADED.
MR. MAYWEATHER.
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT.
[WIND]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
GUARD: YOU, GET BACK TO WORK!
[KOLOS BREATHING HEAVILY]
ARCHER: YOU ALL RIGHT?
KOLOS: PERHAPS I SPENT TOO MUCH
TIME IN THE LAW LIBRARY
AND NOT ENOUGH
IN THE BATTLEFIELD.
ARCHER: NOT ALL KLINGONS
ARE WARRIORS, REMEMBER?
KOLOS: AAH!
GUARD: OUR SHIPS RUN
ON DILITHIUM, NOT TALK.
KOLOS: UH!
ARCHER: LEAVE HIM ALONE.
GUARD: GET BACK TO WORK.
DIFFERENT GUARD:
ANY MORE TROUBLE FROM YOU
AND YOU'LL SPEND THE NIGHT
ON THE SURFACE.
[ARCHER GROANING]
KOLOS: Y-YOU'RE A FOOL.
ARCHER: YOU'RE WELCOME.
KOLOS: HAVEN'T YOU LEARNED
YOUR LESSON?
THIS IS WHY YOU WERE SENT
HERE IN THE FIRST PLACE--
FOR INTERFERING IN AFFAIRS THAT
HAVE NOTHING TO DO WITH YOU.
ARCHER: WE HAVE
A SAYING ON EARTH--
YOU DON'T KICK A MAN
WHEN HE'S DOWN.
KOLOS:
SO ARE ALL HUMANS LIKE THIS?
ARCHER: LIKE WHAT? FAIR?
KOLOS: STUPID.
[LAUGHTER]
ARCHER: IT'S IN OUR NATURE.
KOLOS: STAND UP.
WE HAVE WORK TO DO...
UNLESS YOU WANT TO SLEEP
ON THE SURFACE.
[DOOR OPENS]
GUARD: FOLLOW ME. THIS WAY.
ARCHER: NEW ARRIVALS.
KOLOS: PROSECUTOR ORAK
HAS BEEN BUSY.
STAY AWAY FROM US.
WE HAVE NOTHING YOU WANT.
REED: CAPTAIN!
ARCHER: IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'S FROM MY SHIP.
REED: IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU, SIR.
ARCHER: YOU, TOO.
LIEUTENANT REED,
THIS IS KOLOS, MY ADVOCATE.
[KOLOS GRUNTS]
REED: PLEASURE.
ARCHER: HOW'D YOU GET HERE?
REED: T'POL KNOWS A FEW
KLINGON OFFICIALS
FROM HER DAYS
IN THE MINISTRY OF SECURITY.
ONE OF THEM PUT US IN TOUCH
WITH A CORRECTIONS OFFICER
WHO WAS WILLING TO
LOOK THE OTHER WAY
FOR THE RIGHT PRICE.
I CAME ON ONE
OF THE DILITHIUM BARGES.
WE BRIBED THE CAPTAIN
TO BRING US HERE
AND TAKE US BACK
TO "ENTERPRISE."
ARCHER: IS THERE ROOM
FOR ONE MORE?
REED: I IMAGINE SO.
BUT WE HAVE TO HURRY.
ARCHER: COME ON.
KOLOS: I CAN'T GO WITH YOU.
ARCHER: WHY NOT?
KOLOS: I'VE BEEN AN ADVOCATE
FOR 50 YEARS.
AND I SPENT THE LAST 20 OF THEM
STANDING IN THAT TRIBUNAL,
PLAYING MY PART,
HOLDING MY TONGUE,
AND ALL THE WHILE,
HONORABLE MEN WERE BEING SENT
TO PLACES LIKE THIS
WITHOUT THE BENEFIT
OF A DEFENSE.
AND THEN I WAS
ASSIGNED YOUR CASE.
YOU TOLD ME THAT ON YOUR WORLD,
A FEW COURAGEOUS PEOPLE
MADE A DIFFERENCE.
I'M NOT SURE
I HAVE THE COURAGE,
BUT I KNOW I'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO RESTORE HONOR TO MY PEOPLE
LIVING AS A FUGITIVE.
ARCHER:
YOU REALIZE WHAT THAT MEANS.
YOU SAID MOST PRISONERS HERE
DON'T SURVIVE A YEAR.
KOLOS: MOST PRISONERS HERE HAVE
VERY LITTLE TO LIVE FOR.
REED: CAPTAIN?
KOLOS: GO.
GO!
ARCHER: THANK YOU.