[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI: Bridge to Mayweather.
TRAVIS: MAYWEATHER.
HOSHI: The captain wants you
to report to the bridge.
Admiral Forrest called
a few minutes ago.
We're reversing course.
TRAVIS: I'M ON MY WAY.
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA
BEND OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
T'POL:
THE PLANET'S ORBIT HAS SHIFTED,
TAKING IT BETWEEN
TWO GAS GIANTS.
THEIR GRAVITATIONAL PULL IS
CAUSING ITS CORE TO SUPERHEAT.
ARCHER: STARFLEET THINKS
IT'LL BE COVERED
WITH ERUPTING VOLCANOES
BY THE END OF THE WEEK.
TRAVIS: THIS SYSTEM'S ALMOST
30 LIGHT-YEARS BEHIND US.
ARCHER: ADMIRAL FORREST ASSURES
ME IT'S ONLY A TEMPORARY DETOUR.
TUCKER: SOME GEOLOGIC FIREWORKS.
COULD BE FUN.
ARCHER: SET A COURSE.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
TRAVIS:
DO YOU HAVE A MINUTE, SIR?
ARCHER: SEVERAL, ACTUALLY.
PLEASE.
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
TRAVIS: I WAS WONDERING IF
I COULD MAKE A PERSONAL REQUEST.
ARCHER: OF COURSE.
TRAVIS: MY FAMILY'S
SHIP, "THE "HORIZON"--
WE'RE GOING TO BE
PASSING CLOSE TO IT.
I WOULDN'T MIND
GOING BY FOR A VISIT.
IT'S ABOUT 10 HOURS
OFF OUR FLIGHT PATH.
"ENTERPRISE" CAN STILL GET TO
THE PLANET WITH TIME TO SPARE.
YOU COULD PICK ME UP
ON THE WAY BACK.
ARCHER: I THINK WE CAN MANAGE
WITHOUT YOU FOR A FEW DAYS.
TRAVIS: THANK YOU, SIR.
ARCHER: YOUR FOLKS WILL BE
SURPRISED TO SEE YOU.
TRAVIS: MY FATHER'S BEEN
ILL FOR A FEW MONTHS.
ARCHER: NOTHING SERIOUS, I HOPE.
TRAVIS:
MY MOTHER SAID HE'LL BE FINE.
SHE'S THE SHIP'S MEDIC.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT YOU TOLD ME
YOUR MOTHER WAS
THE CHIEF ENGINEER.
TRAVIS: SHE'S BOTH.
ARCHER: I GUESS THEY HAVE
TO WEAR A LOT OF HATS
TO KEEP THOSE OLD SHIPS RUNNING.
TRAVIS: MY GRANDFATHER
HELD THE RECORD--
5 JOBS AT ONE TIME,
TWO OF THEM ON THE BRIDGE.
ARCHER: THERE WAS A TIME
WHEN I GAVE SERIOUS THOUGHT
TO SERVING ON A CARGO SHIP.
TRAVIS: YOU, SIR?
ARCHER: IT WAS A FEW YEARS
BEFORE STARFLEET WAS CHARTERED.
TRAVIS: WHY DIDN'T YOU SIGN UP?
ARCHER: LONG STORY.
I'LL TELL YOU THE NEXT TIME
WE HAVE BREAKFAST.
AFTER WE DOCK, I'LL
HAVE PHLOX GO OVER WITH YOU,
HAVE HIM TAKE A LOOK
AT YOUR FATHER.
TRAVIS:
I'D APPRECIATE THAT, SIR.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
TUCKER: YOU'LL BE GLAD TO HEAR
THE THERMAL SCANNERS
ARE UP AND RUNNING.
T'POL: AND THE IMAGING RELAYS?
TUCKER: YEP. WE'LL DROP SIX
OF THEM IN HIGH ORBIT.
THAT SHOULD GIVE US
A BIRD'S-EYE VIEW
OF EVERY VOLCANO
ON THE PLANET.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S NOT GONNA BE
A LOT TO DO ONCE WE GET THERE.
SENSORS WILL RECORD
EVERYTHING AUTOMATICALLY.
T'POL:
YOU SHOULD HAVE PLENTY OF TIME
TO PRACTICE YOUR HARMONICA.
TUCKER: I'VE TALKED CHEF
INTO DOING SOMETHING SPECIAL.
STARTING TUESDAY, IT'S GONNA
BE MOVIE NIGHT EVERY NIGHT.
THOUGHT YOU MIGHT BE INTERESTED,
SEEING HOW YOU ENJOYED
THAT WESTERN.
WE'RE GONNA BE SHOWING
THE THREE GREATEST
HORROR MOVIES EVER MADE:
"FRANKENSTEIN,"
"BRIDE OF FRANKENSTEIN,"
AND "SON OF FRANKENSTEIN."
WE MIGHT EVEN THROW IN "ABBOTT
AND COSTELLO MEET FRANKENSTEIN."
T'POL: I HAVE NO INTEREST
IN HORROR MOVIES.
TUCKER: HOW DO YOU KNOW
IF YOU'VE NEVER SEEN ONE?
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO SEE ALL OF THEM.
JUST COME THE FIRST NIGHT.
I PROMISE YOU'LL LIKE IT.
REANIMATED LIFE-FORMS,
SCIENCE RUN AMOK--
THEY'RE RIGHT UP YOUR ALLEY.
REED: FOUR YEARS ISN'T SO LONG.
MY LAST FAMILY REUNION
WAS ALMOST A DECADE AGO.
TRAVIS:
STARFLEET REALLY OUGHT TO THINK
ABOUT PUTTING FAMILIES
ON STARSHIPS.
REED: YOU MUST BE JOKING.
TRAVIS:
NO ONE WOULD EVER GET HOMESICK.
REED: YES.
WELL, THEY'D BETTER
POST A PSYCHOLOGIST ONBOARD,
BECAUSE I'D NEED ONE
IF MY PARENTS WERE
ROAMING THE CORRIDORS.
TRAVIS: ON A CARGO SHIP,
YOU CAN'T WALK 10 METERS
WITHOUT RUNNING INTO YOUR
BABYSITTER OR A GREAT-AUNT.
HOSHI:
Bridge to Ensign Mayweather.
TRAVIS: GO AHEAD.
HOSHI: We've gotten a response
from the "Horizon."
It's your mother.
TRAVIS: THANKS, HOSHI.
PUT IT THROUGH TO MY QUARTERS.
ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S PERSONAL LOG,
JANUARY 10, 2153.
WE'RE ON COURSE FOR OUR
RENDEZVOUS WITH THE "HORIZON."
UNFORTUNATELY,
I'VE JUST RECEIVED WORD
THAT ENSIGN MAYWEATHER'S FAMILY
IS FACING
AN UNEXPECTED TRAGEDY.
MIND IF I JOIN YOU?
TRAVIS: OF COURSE NOT.
ARCHER: I HAVEN'T BEEN UP HERE
SINCE WE LAUNCHED.
COME HERE A LOT?
TRAVIS: EVERY NOW AND THEN.
ARCHER: COMMANDER TUCKER
TOLD ME WHAT HAPPENED.
I'M SORRY.
TRAVIS: MY MOTHER SENT
A MESSAGE TO STARFLEET
SIX WEEKS AGO.
BUT I NEVER GOT IT.
ARCHER: THE CIVILIAN CHANNELS
CAN BE PRETTY SLOW.
TRAVIS:
I SHOULD HAVE CALLED HIM.
WE WERE IN COMM RANGE
A FEW MONTHS AGO.
I GUESS I WASN'T READY
TO TALK TO HIM YET.
HE WASN'T VERY HAPPY WITH ME
WHEN I JOINED STARFLEET.
HE'D BEEN GROOMING ME
FOR HIS JOB...
SINCE I WAS A KID.
ARCHER: I'M SURE.
IT WASN'T EASY FOR HIM
WHEN YOU LEFT.
BUT I KNOW FOR A FACT...
THAT HE WAS PROUD OF YOU.
TRAVIS:
WITH ALL RESPECT, SIR...
I'M NOT SO SURE HE WAS.
ARCHER: DID HE EVER TELL YOU
ABOUT THE LETTER HE SENT ME?
IT WAS ALMOST 2 1/2 YEARS AGO.
THERE WERE A FEW CANDIDATES I
WAS LOOKING AT FOR HELM OFFICER.
I WAS HAVING
A LITTLE TROUBLE DECIDING,
SO I CONTACTED
THEIR FORMER C.O.s,
HOPING FOR
A MORE PERSONAL EVALUATION.
TRAVIS: WHAT DID HE SAY?
ARCHER: HE WROTE
THE SHORTEST RECOMMENDATION--
JUST ONE SENTENCE.
HE SAID...
HE'D NEVER MET A MORE
NATURAL STICK-AND-RUDDER MAN
IN HIS LIFE,
AND I'D BE A FOOL
IF I DIDN'T CHOOSE YOU.
WHEN I SAW HOW YOU HANDLED
YOURSELF AT THE HELM...
I KNEW HE WAS RIGHT.
TRAVIS: I WISH...
HE WOULD HAVE TOLD ME THAT.
PHLOX: AS I SUSPECTED.
IT'S NOTHING MORE
THAN A SIMPLE HEADACHE.
T'POL: I WAS HOPING
FOR SOMETHING MORE SERIOUS.
PHLOX: OH?
T'POL: I'VE BEEN COERCED
INTO WATCHING TONIGHT'S MOVIE.
PHLOX: AH, IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A MEDICAL EXCUSE,
I'M AFRAID YOU'RE OUT OF LUCK.
IF IT'S ANY CONSOLATION,
I'LL BE THERE AS WELL.
I AGREE THIS FORM OF
ENTERTAINMENT IS RATHER CRUDE,
BUT IT CAN OFTEN PROVIDE
AN ENLIGHTENING GLIMPSE
INTO HUMAN BEHAVIOR.
T'POL: DON'T BE SURPRISED
IF YOU SEE ME
HERE AGAIN AFTERWARDS.
I HAVE LITTLE DOUBT
MY HEADACHE WILL RETURN.
TUCKER: JUST A QUICK TOUR
OF THE ENGINE ROOM,
THAT'S ALL I'M ASKING.
THE "HORIZON'S" 50 YEARS OLD.
I'M SURE YOU'VE SEEN FAR
MORE IMPRESSIVE WARP REACTORS.
TUCKER: ZEFRAM COCHRANE DESIGNED
THAT ENGINE HIMSELF.
I'VE HEARD RUMORS
THAT HE PERSONALLY SIGNED
THE INSIDE
OF EACH REACTOR CASING.
OH, UH...ALMOST FORGOT.
TRAVIS: WHAT'S THIS?
TUCKER: A FEW FAMILY PHOTOS.
I DOWNLOADED EVERY PICTURE I'VE
TAKEN SINCE WE LEFT SPACEDOCK.
THOUGHT YOUR MOM MIGHT LIKE TO
SEE WHAT HER BOY'S BEEN UP TO.
TRAVIS: THANK YOU, SIR.
TUCKER: YOU BET.
TRAVIS: I WOULDN'T CALL IT
A DANGEROUS MISSION.
WE'VE GOTTEN INTO
A FEW SKIRMISHES,
BUT NOTHING
WE COULDN'T HANDLE.
RIANNA: I GOT A LETTER
FROM YOUR SISTER.
SHE SAID YOU MENTIONED
A CLOSE CALL
WITH SOME KIND OF STORM.
TRAVIS: WE RAN INTO A SMALL
WAVE FRONT A FEW MONTHS AGO.
THE CREW HAD TO SQUEEZE
INTO ONE OF THE NACELLES
FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS.
SHE PROBABLY MADE IT
SOUND WORSE THAN IT WAS.
RIANNA:
SHE ALSO MENTIONED SOMETHING
ABOUT ALIEN SOLDIERS
FORCING THEIR WAY ABOARD.
TRAVIS: IT WAS REALLY JUST
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
THEY THOUGHT "ENTERPRISE"
HAD BEEN ABANDONED.
CAPTAIN ARCHER CONVINCED THEM
TO LEAVE.
RIANNA: I GUESS THERE'S
NO POINT IN ASKING YOU
ABOUT THE ROMULAN MINEFIELD.
TRAVIS: HOW'D YOU KNOW
ABOUT THAT?
RIANNA: I'VE BEEN SERVING
ON CARGO SHIPS FOR A LONG TIME.
I'VE MADE A FEW CONTACTS
HERE AND THERE.
[ALARM]
CREWMAN: Stand by to go to warp.
[RUMBLING]
TRAVIS:
CHARLIE MUST BE AT THE HELM.
RIANNA: WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
TRAVIS: HIS WARP JUMPS
WERE ALWAYS A LITTLE ROUGH.
[RIANNA LAUGHS]
TRAVIS: WHERE ARE WE HEADED?
RIANNA: DENEVA STATION. JUST
A QUICK RUN TO PICK UP SUPPLIES.
WE'LL HAVE YOU BACK
IN PLENTY OF TIME.
WELDER: WATCH YOUR STEP, MA'AM.
WELDER: TRAVIS?
TRAVIS: HEY!
WELDER:
HAVEN'T SEEN YOU FOR A WHILE.
DID YOU LOCK YOURSELF IN
A CARGO CONTAINER AGAIN?
TRAVIS: DO YOU ALWAYS HAVE
TO BRING THAT UP?
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
HEY. IF YOU'RE NOT BUSY TONIGHT,
STOP BY THE MESS.
TRAVIS: I WILL.
RIANNA: DID YOU FORGET YOUR WAY?
TRAVIS: GUEST QUARTERS
ARE OVER HERE.
RIANNA: YOU'RE NOT ASSIGNED
TO GUEST QUARTERS.
TRAVIS: I THOUGHT MY ROOM
HAD BEEN REASSIGNED.
RIANNA:
IT WAS, BUT THEY DIDN'T MIND
GIVING IT UP FOR A FEW DAYS.
WE DON'T GET V.I.P.s VERY OFTEN.
I FOUND SOME
OF YOUR OLD THINGS.
THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
FEEL MORE AT HOME.
TRAVIS: I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU KEPT THIS.
RIANNA: YOU STAYED UP
ALL NIGHT FOR A MONTH,
MAPPING EVERY SYSTEM
YOU PLANNED TO VISIT
WHEN YOU GREW UP.
TRAVIS:
I'VE STILL GOT A WAYS TO GO.
RIANNA: I'M GLAD YOU'RE HOME.
TRAVIS: ME, TOO.
WE'RE GOING TO GET
THROUGH THIS, MOM.
[RIANNA SIGHS]
THOSE, UH, PLASMA INJECTORS
AREN'T GOING TO ALIGN
THEMSELVES.
I SHOULD GO.
OH, AFTER YOU'VE SETTLED IN,
UH, COME BY THE ENGINE ROOM.
SOME PEOPLE WANT TO SAY HELLO.
PAUL: TRANSFER THESE
CANISTERS OVER TO MODULE 4.
CREWMAN: MM-HMM.
TRAVIS: ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE OLD
ENOUGH TO DRIVE THAT THING?
PAUL: AN ENSIGN OUGHT TO SALUTE
BEFORE ADDRESSING A CAPTAIN.
TRAVIS: ACTING CAPTAIN.
DON'T LET IT GO TO YOUR HEAD.
PAUL: I'LL CATCH UP WITH YOU
IN A FEW MINUTES.
TRAVIS:
THE JACKET LOOKS GOOD ON YOU.
PAUL: THANKS.
DIDN'T THINK I'D BE
WEARING IT THIS SOON.
TRAVIS: BUSINESS MUST BE GOOD.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THIS MODULE SO FULL.
PAUL:
THE BIGGEST PROBLEM THESE DAYS
IS KEEPING TRACK OF EVERYTHING.
DAD KEPT A LOT OF
THE INVENTORY IN HIS HEAD.
I'M TRYING TO RECONSTRUCT
THE DATABASE.
WE STILL CAN'T FIND
THE STROMATOPOD LARVAE
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE DELIVERING
TO THE DEMERIANS.
I ONLY HOPE IT DIDN'T END UP
IN COLD STORAGE.
TRAVIS: IF YOU NEED
ME TO HELP OUT WITH ANYTHING--
PAUL:
THANKS, BUT WE CAN HANDLE IT.
YOU'RE ON LEAVE.
I'M NOT GONNA PUT YOU TO WORK.
TRAVIS: SEE YOU AT DINNER?
PAUL: TRAVIS.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO CHANGE
INTO SOMETHING
A LITTLE LESS CONSPICUOUS.
T'POL: I'VE DEPLOYED
THE IMAGING RELAYS.
ARCHER: HOW LONG UNTIL
THE SHOW BEGINS?
T'POL: APPROXIMATELY 30 HOURS.
THE HOLOMETRIC CAMERA
STILL NEEDS TO BE CALIBRATED.
TUCKER: I CAN HELP WITH THAT.
ARCHER: GET STARTED.
I'D LIKE TO SHARE OUR PICTURES
WITH STARFLEET,
GIVE ADMIRAL FORREST
A FRONT-ROW SEAT.
HOSHI: ECHO III's WITHIN RANGE.
IT SHOULDN'T BE TOO HARD
TO SET UP A DOWNLINK.
TUCKER: SO YOU COMING TONIGHT?
T'POL: IF THESE SENSORS
ARE CALIBRATED BY THEN.
TUCKER: WELL, YOU BETTER
MAKE UP YOUR MIND.
SEATS ARE GONNA FILL UP FAST.
T'POL:
ACCORDING TO THE DATABASE,
"FRANKENSTEIN" IS ALSO
A WORK OF LITERATURE.
TUCKER: MARY SHELLEY WROTE IT,
THE WIFE OF A FAMOUS POET.
T'POL:
PERHAPS A DRAMATIC READING
WOULD BE MORE ILLUMINATING.
TUCKER: YOU EXPECT A MESS HALL
FULL OF CREWMEN
TO SIT STILL WHILE SOMEONE
READS TO THEM?
T'POL: THEY'D BE MORE LIKELY
TO APPRECIATE THE AUTHOR'S
TRUE INTENT.
TUCKER: YOU WANT TO START
A BOOK CLUB, GO RIGHT AHEAD.
YOU'RE GONNA BE THERE
TONIGHT, AREN'T YOU, SIR?
ARCHER: WOULDN'T MISS IT.
TUCKER: WELL, I'LL SAVE YOU
SOME POPCORN.
ARCHER: MIGHT BE A GOOD IDEA
FOR YOU TO GO, TOO.
IT MIGHT BE FUN,
AND A LITTLE FRATERNIZING
COULDN'T HURT.
T'POL: I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW SITTING SILENTLY
IN A DARKENED ROOM
CONSTITUTES FRATERNIZING.
ARCHER:
IT'S A COMMUNAL EXPERIENCE.
TELL YOU WHAT.
LET'S MAKE A NIGHT OF IT--
DINNER IN THE CAPTAIN'S MESS,
1800, MOVIE AT 1930.
YOU'LL BE MY DATE.
T'POL: I BEG YOUR PARDON.
ARCHER:
I'LL BE A PERFECT GENTLEMAN.
AND IF YOU DON'T
LIKE THE MOVIE,
I'LL NEVER ASK YOU TO SIT
THROUGH ANOTHER ONE.
TRAVIS: ALL RIGHT.
TRY IT NOW.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
NICHOLS: MM-HMM.
TRAVIS: I'VE INCREASED THE RANGE
OF THE NAVIGATION SENSORS.
THE HELM WILL MAKE COURSE
CORRECTIONS A LOT QUICKER.
PAUL: WHAT'S WRONG?
TRAVIS: I'M JUST WORKING
ON A FEW UPGRADES.
PAUL: I DON'T REMEMBER ASKING
FOR ANY UPGRADES.
TRAVIS: YOU WERE BUSY.
I DIDN'T WANT TO BOTHER YOU.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE THIS.
YOU KNOW THOSE PORT STABILIZERS
THAT WERE ALWAYS ACTING UP?
BEFORE I LEFT, I SPOKE
WITH COMMANDER TUCKER.
PAUL: COMMANDER TUCKER?
TRAVIS: OUR CHIEF ENGINEER
ON "ENTERPRISE."
HE SHOWED ME HOW TO RECONFIGURE
THE SPATIAL DISCRIMINATORS.
THEY SHOULDN'T GIVE YOU
ANY MORE TROUBLE.
PAUL: WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
IF THESE IMPROVEMENTS OF YOURS
GO OFFLINE?
YOU'LL BE BACK ON YOUR STARFLEET
SHIP, OUT OF COMM RANGE.
WHO'S GONNA FIX IT?
I'D PREFER IT IF YOU DIDN'T
MODIFY ANY MORE SYSTEMS
WITHOUT DISCUSSING IT WITH ME.
TRAVIS: WHATEVER YOU SAY...SIR.
PAUL: MAYBE YOU CAN STOP
BY ENGINEERING...
BUILD US A WARP 5 ENGINE.
[DOOR BUZZES]
TRAVIS: COME IN.
NORA: I HEARD WE HAD A VISITOR.
TRAVIS: WORD TRAVELS FAST.
[NORA LAUGHING]
NORA: I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE
HE'S GONE.
I'M SO SORRY, TRAVIS.
TRAVIS: THANKS.
NORA: AREN'T YOU A LITTLE OLD
FOR THIS?
TRAVIS: I DON'T KNOW.
I THOUGHT IT MIGHT BE FUN
TO REGRESS FOR A WHILE.
WHAT DO YOU SAY WE TURN OFF
THE GRAV PLATING
AND JUMP ON THE BED?
NORA: AND GET GROUNDED AGAIN?
THAT WOULDN'T LOOK TOO GOOD
ON YOUR STARFLEET RECORD.
[LAUGHTER]
HOW'S "ENTERPRISE"?
TRAVIS: KEEPS US BUSY.
WE'VE GONE 150 LIGHT-YEARS,
SEEN 22 INHABITED WORLDS.
NORA: IN 18 MONTHS?
TRAVIS: YOU CAN'T BELIEVE
WHAT'S OUT THERE.
NORA: COLUMBUS, MAGELLAN,
TRAVIS MAYWEATHER.
[NORA LAUGHING]
HOW LONG ARE YOU HOME FOR?
TRAVIS: JUST A FEW DAYS.
NORA: ANY CHANCE OF GETTING
AN EXTENDED LEAVE?
TRAVIS: I'M AFRAID NOT.
I DOUBT MAGELLAN GOT
MUCH TIME OFF, EITHER.
WHAT'S WRONG?
NORA: I DON'T MEAN TO SPOIL
YOUR VISIT, BUT...
THINGS HAVEN'T EXACTLY
BEEN RUNNING LIKE CLOCKWORK
SINCE YOUR FATHER DIED.
TRAVIS: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
NORA: WE MISSED A RENDEZVOUS
WITH AN ORION FREIGHTER
2 WEEKS AGO.
THE CARGO AUTHORITY
WASN'T TOO PLEASED.
WE'RE ALSO LOW ON DEUTERIUM.
WE'VE HAD TO DIP INTO
THE RESERVES TWICE THIS MONTH.
MORALE'S BEEN BETTER, TRAVIS.
"HORIZON'S" LOST ITS CAPTAIN,
AND SOME OF THE CREW
ARE STARTING TO WONDER
IF PAUL'S READY FOR THE JOB.
YOU MIGHT HAVE NOTICED
HE'S BEEN A LITTLE ON EDGE.
TRAVIS: HE'S ALWAYS ON EDGE.
NORA: MORE THAN USUAL.
TRAVIS: MY MOTHER HASN'T
MENTIONED ANY OF THIS.
NORA: I GUESS SHE DIDN'T
WANT TO WORRY YOU.
TRAVIS: HE'S ONLY BEEN
IN COMMAND A FEW WEEKS.
GIVE HIM A CHANCE.
HE'LL GROW INTO IT.
NORA: I HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M SURE THIS IS THE LAST THING
YOU WANTED TO HEAR RIGHT NOW.
I THOUGHT YOU SHOULD KNOW.
TRAVIS: THANKS.
[RUMBLING]
CHARLIE AT THE HELM?
NORA: JUST A LITTLE
SPATIAL TURBULENCE.
YOU'VE GOTTEN SPOILED
ON "ENTERPRISE."
[WEAPON FIRING]
TRAVIS: THAT'S NO TURBULENCE.
NICHOLS:
HULL FRACTURE IN MODULE 3.
WE'RE VENTING ATMOSPHERE.
PAUL: SEAL IT OFF.
TRY HAILING THEM AGAIN.
NICHOLS:
THEY'RE STILL NOT RESPONDING.
TRAVIS: WHAT'S GOING ON?
PAUL: WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
TRAVIS: BY WHO?
PAUL: I DON'T KNOW.
NICHOLS: SHOULD I ARM
THE PLASMA TURRETS?
PAUL: NO.
TRANSFER RESERVE POWER
TO THE HULL PLATING.
WE NEED TO GET OUT OF
THEIR WEAPONS RANGE.
GO TO MAXIMUM WARP.
TRAVIS: YOU'RE HAULING
30,000 METRIC TONS.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO BE
ABLE TO OUTRUN THEM.
PAUL: YOU HEARD ME.
NICHOLS: YES, SIR.
WARP 1.6.
1.7.
WARP 1.8.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE STILL CLOSING.
PAUL: A LITTLE MORE.
NICHOLS: 1.85.
THEY'RE MOVING OFF.
PAUL: REDUCE SPEED TO 1.5.
TRAVIS: THEY ATTACHED SOMETHING
TO THE HULL.
PAUL: SHOW ME.
NICHOLS: IT'S EMITTING
A SUBSPACE SIGNAL.
COULD BE SOME KIND OF BEACON.
PAUL: CALL ENGINEERING.
TELL THEM TO GET SOMEONE
OUT THERE TO PRY IT OFF.
TRAVIS: I WOULDN'T
RECOMMEND THAT.
THIS IS A DICOBALT SIGNATURE--
A HIGH-YIELD EXPLOSIVE.
IF ANYONE GETS TOO CLOSE,
IT MIGHT DECIDE TO GO OFF.
NICHOLS: THE "CONSTELLATION"
SENT US THIS.
THIS SHIP ATTACKED THEM
EIGHT WEEKS AGO,
AND IT PLANTED A BEACON
ON THEIR HULL.
A DAY LATER,
THIS CRUISER SHOWED UP
AND DEMANDED THEIR CARGO.
THE "CONSTELLATION" TRIED
TO DRIVE THEM OFF,
BUT THE ALIENS GOT ABOARD
AND KILLED THREE OF THEIR CREW.
THEN THEY TOOK
THE ENTIRE SHIPMENT.
TRAVIS: WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS
DOES THE "CONSTELLATION" HAVE?
NICHOLS: TWO PLASMA TURRETS,
SAME AS US.
PAUL: THERE HAS TO BE A WAY
TO REMOVE THAT BEACON.
RIANNA: I WOULDN'T RISK IT.
IF IT DETONATES,
YOU COULD LOSE THE NACELLE.
PAUL: IF WE JETTISON
A FEW TONS OF THAT ORE,
CAN WE INCREASE TO WARP 2?
RIANNA: I DON'T SEE WHY NOT.
PAUL: THAT SHOULD ALLOW US
TO REACH DENEVA STATION
AHEAD OF SCHEDULE.
IT'S WELL-ARMED.
WE SHOULD BE SAFE THERE.
TRAVIS: WHAT HAPPENS IF THEY
COME BACK BEFORE WE ARRIVE?
PAUL: THERE'S NO OTHER CHOICE.
WE CAN'T SHOOT OUR WAY
OUT OF THIS.
TRAVIS: I'VE SEEN THIS KIND
OF ENGINE CONFIGURATION BEFORE.
IT'S NOT THAT DIFFERENT
FROM A MAZARITE SHIP.
RIANNA: MAZARITE?
TRAVIS: WE HAD
SOME TROUBLE WITH THEM.
WE MANAGED TO KNOCK OUT
THEIR ENGINES
WITH OUR PHASE CANNONS.
PAUL:
WE DON'T HAVE PHASE CANNONS.
TRAVIS:
I CAN TIE THE PLASMA TURRETS
DIRECTLY INTO
THE IMPULSE ENGINES.
LIEUTENANT REED DID THAT,
AND IT INCREASED
OUR YIELD BY 80%.
PAUL: I'M NOT GONNA RISK
ALL OF OUR LIVES
BY GETTING INTO A FIGHT
WE CAN'T WIN.
IF THEY REACH US BEFORE
WE MAKE IT TO DENEVA,
WE'LL GIVE THEM
WHAT THEY WANT.
TRAVIS: IF THERE'S ONE THING
I'VE LEARNED
FROM CAPTAIN ARCHER,
IT'S THAT YOU DON'T GIVE IN
TO PEOPLE LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE ONLY GOING TO
ENCOURAGE MORE ATTACKS,
NOT JUST AGAINST YOU
BUT OTHER CARGO SHIPS.
PAUL: I APPRECIATE THE ADVICE,
BUT THIS ISN'T YOUR PROBLEM.
YOU'RE NOT PART
OF THIS CREW ANYMORE.
JETTISON THAT ORE
AND INCREASE OUR SPEED.
RIANNA: EVEN YOUR FATHER
HAD TO MAKE COMPROMISES.
THE SAFEST THING TO DO
IS GIVE THEM WHAT THEY WANT.
CARGO CAN BE REPLACED.
DOCTOR FRANKENSTEIN: FOOL.
IF THIS STORM DEVELOPS
AS I HOPE,
YOU WILL HAVE PLENTY
TO BE AFRAID OF
BEFORE THE NIGHT'S OVER.
GO ON. FIX THE ELECTRODES.
THIS STORM WILL BE MAGNIFICENT.
ALL THE ELECTRICAL SECRETS
OF HEAVEN.
THIS TIME WE'RE READY.
EH, FRITZ?
READY.
[THUNDER]
ARCHER: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
T'POL: REVIEWING THIS MORNING'S
SENSOR DATA.
ARCHER: I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GONNA GIVE THIS A CHANCE.
DR. FRANKENSTEIN:
JUST A FEW STITCHES.
LOOK, HERE'S
THE FINAL TOUCH--
A BRAIN YOU STOLE, FRITZ.
FRITZ: YES.
FRANKENSTEIN: THINK OF IT--
THE BRAIN OF A DEAD MAN...
PHLOX: THIS DR. FRANKENSTEIN--
HIS TECHNIQUE IS NOT DISSIMILAR
TO A PRACTICE ON B'SAARI II.
THEY SUCCESSFULLY USED
AN ISOLYTIC CURRENT
TO REANIMATE THE BODIES
OF THE RECENTLY DECEASED.
TUCKER: REALLY?
PHLOX: MM-HMM.
OF COURSE,
THE REVIVED INDIVIDUALS
WEREN'T CAPABLE OF MORE
THAN BASIC CELLULAR METABOLISM.
HOWEVER, THE B'SAARI
HAVE DEVELOPED A PROCEDURE
THAT, UH, SHOWS PROMISE
IN REPAIRING THE SYNAPTIC, UH...
T'POL: WE CAN STOP THE FILM
IF IT'S DISTURBING
YOUR CONVERSATION.
[PHLOX CLEARS THROAT]
[THUNDER]
DR. FRANKENSTEIN:
IN 15 MINUTES, THE STORM
SHOULD BE AT ITS HEIGHT.
THEN WE'LL BE READY.
WHAT'S THAT NOISE?
[TAPPING]
NICHOLS: CAPTAIN?
LOOKS LIKE SOMEONE'S REROUTING
THE IMPULSE RELAYS.
PAUL: WHERE?
NICHOLS: MODULE 5.
PAUL: YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE.
I THOUGHT I MADE MYSELF CLEAR.
TRAVIS: IF THOSE ALIENS
COME BACK, YOU'LL THANK ME.
PAUL: I TOLD YOU, I'M NOT GOING
TO TAKE THIS SHIP INTO BATTLE.
TRAVIS: YOU MAY NOT
HAVE A CHOICE.
PAUL: I DIDN'T ASK
FOR YOUR OPINION,
AND I DIDN'T APPROVE
YOUR MODIFICATIONS.
STOP WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
TRAVIS: PAUL.
PAUL: YOU HEARD ME.
TRAVIS: I DIDN'T MEAN
TO UNDERMINE YOUR AUTHORITY.
PAUL: REALLY?
TRAVIS: BUT YOU'RE
BEING UNREASONABLE.
I JUST WANT US TO BE PREPARED.
PAUL: US?
YOU KEEP TALKING AS IF
YOU'RE A PART OF THIS CREW.
TRAVIS: IT'S STILL MY HOME.
PAUL: YOU TURNED YOUR BACK ON US
A LONG TIME AGO.
TRAVIS: IS THAT WHAT THIS IS
ABOUT--ME LEAVING?
IF YOU WANT TO BE
AN EFFECTIVE CAPTAIN,
YOU'VE GOT TO SET
YOUR PERSONAL FEELINGS ASIDE,
LISTEN TO WHAT OTHER PEOPLE
HAVE TO SAY.
PAUL: MORE WORDS OF WISDOM
FROM STARFLEET?
TRAVIS: NO, YOUR FATHER.
HE SAID THAT TO ME
A LONG TIME AGO.
IF HE WAS HERE NOW,
HE'D TELL YOU THE SAME THING.
PAUL: YOU QUOTING DAD?
YOU NEVER LISTENED TO HIM.
IF YOU HAD, YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE ABANDONED YOUR FAMILY.
YOU BARELY SPOKE TO HIM
FOR THE LAST FOUR YEARS.
YOU WEREN'T EVEN HERE
WHEN HE DIED.
TRAVIS: THAT ISN'T FAIR.
PAUL: YOU KNEW HE WAS SICK.
BUT YOU DIDN'T REALLY CARE.
YOU ONLY DECIDED TO STOP BY
BECAUSE IT WAS CONVENIENT
FOR YOU.
HOSTILE ALIENS
AREN'T OUR PROBLEM.
IT'S STARFLEET
AND PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA HOW
HARD IT IS TO FIND NEW CREWMEN?
NO ONE WANTS TO RUN
FREIGHT ANYMORE.
THEY ALL WANT TO BE EXPLORERS,
CRUISING AROUND
ON STATE-OF-THE-ART SHIPS
WITH THEIR PERSONAL CHEFS.
TRAVIS: YOU WANT TO STAND AROUND
FEELING SORRY FOR YOURSELF,
GO AHEAD.
I'VE GOT BETTER THINGS TO DO.
PAUL: TAKE THOSE
UPGRADES OFFLINE.
I'LL CONFINE YOU
TO QUARTERS IF I HAVE TO.
TRAVIS: I'M JUST TRYING
TO HELP YOU, PAUL.
IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
YOU COULD USE A LITTLE HELP
RIGHT NOW.
PAUL: I DON'T WANT YOUR HELP.
TRAVIS:
YOU WANT TO TAKE THEM OFFLINE?
DO IT YOURSELF.
RIANNA: I UNDERSTAND YOU MADE
A FEW MODIFICATIONS
TO THE IMPULSE RELAYS.
NEXT TIME, YOU MIGHT
WANT TO CHECK WITH ME.
I AM THE CHIEF ENGINEER.
TRAVIS: I KNEW
HOW PAUL WOULD REACT,
AND I DIDN'T WANT
TO DRAG YOU INTO IT.
[RIANNA CHUCKLES]
RIANNA: I'VE PLAYED REFEREE
BETWEEN YOU AND YOUR BROTHER
FOR A LONG TIME.
TRAVIS: NEVER THOUGHT I'D
ACTUALLY MISS THESE.
RIANNA: NUTRI-PAKS?
TRAVIS: NOT
JUST ANY NUTRI-PAK--
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE.
THE FIRST TIME
I TASTED REAL SHORTCAKE
WAS IN SAN FRANCISCO.
IT JUST WASN'T THE SAME.
[RIANNA CHUCKLES]
RIANNA: I THINK THEY'VE RUINED
YOUR TASTE BUDS.
TRAVIS: I WOULDN'T MIND
EATING LIKE THIS AGAIN.
I'M THINKING ABOUT ASKING
FOR AN EXTENDED LEAVE.
I'M SURE CAPTAIN ARCHER
WOULD APPROVE, CONSIDERING.
RIANNA:
HOW LONG WOULD YOU STAY?
TRAVIS:
AS LONG AS I'M NEEDED.
RIANNA:
BUT YOU'RE NEEDED ON YOUR SHIP.
TRAVIS:
I'M NOT THE ONLY HELM OFFICER.
RIANNA: EVEN IF YOUR CAPTAIN
AGREES, IT COULD BE A LONG TIME
BEFORE "ENTERPRISE" IS
BACK THIS WAY AGAIN.
TRAVIS:
THERE'S A LOT FOR ME TO DO HERE.
I CAN HELP UPGRADE
THE GUIDANCE AND WARP SYSTEMS.
WITH A LITTLE LUCK,
WE COULD MAKE "HORIZON"
THE FASTEST J-CLASS
IN THE FLEET.
RIANNA: YOU'RE GONNA GIVE UP
YOUR CAREER, MOVE BACK HOME,
AND TAKE ORDERS
FROM YOUR BROTHER?
TRAVIS: MY CAREER'S THE LAST
THING ON MY MIND RIGHT NOW.
RIANNA:
HA HA! OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
NOW YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S
LIKE TO BE A PARENT.
[RIANNA CHUCKLES]
I COULD SPEND EVERY WAKING
MINUTE WORRYING ABOUT YOU TWO.
BUT I'D NEVER GET
ANY WORK DONE.
TRAVIS: HE'S NOT READY, MOM.
RIANNA: YOU SHOULD'VE SEEN YOUR
FATHER WHEN HE TOOK OVER.
HE WAS A YEAR YOUNGER
THAN PAUL IS NOW.
HE WAS AN ENGINEER.
HE DIDN'T KNOW THE FIRST THING
ABOUT RUNNING A BRIDGE.
WE FELL SO FAR BEHIND SCHEDULE,
HE ALMOST LOST
HIS E.C.A. LICENSE.
HE WANTED TO QUIT.
I WOULDN'T LET HIM.
YOUR BROTHER
JUST NEEDS SOME TIME.
TRAVIS: YOU DON'T THINK
I SHOULD STAY?
RIANNA: DIDN'T WE HAVE
THIS CONVERSATION?
IT WAS RIGHT HERE IN THIS ROOM,
FOUR YEARS AGO,
WHEN YOU FIRST THOUGHT
ABOUT JOINING STARFLEET.
TRAVIS: A LOT HAS CHANGED
IN FOUR YEARS, MOM.
RIANNA: THAT'S TRUE, AND A LOT
MORE'S GOING TO CHANGE.
WILL WE BE TALKING ABOUT THIS
AGAIN IN ANOTHER FOUR YEARS?
YOU'RE THE HELMSMAN OF
THE FIRST WARP 5 STARSHIP.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
EVERYONE HERE IS--
EVEN PAUL,
THOUGH HE WON'T ADMIT IT.
IF YOU'LL INDULGE
A LITTLE MOTHERLY ADVICE,
DON'T LET YOUR GUILT OVER
LEAVING GUIDE YOUR DECISION.
TRAVIS:
I'LL TRY TO KEEP THAT IN MIND.
GOOD NIGHT.
RIANNA: GOOD NIGHT.
[TUCKER CHUCKLES]
TUCKER: I FIND IT HARD
TO BELIEVE
THAT NO ONE ON VULCAN'S EVER
HEARD OF A HORROR MOVIE.
T'POL:
THERE IS SOMETHING SIMILAR--
A DISCIPLINE
KNOWN AS TARUL-ETEK.
IT USES DISTURBING IMAGERY TO
PROVOKE AN EMOTIONAL RESPONSE.
ARCHER: THEY TRY AND SCARE YOU
TO SEE HOW WELL YOU
SUPPRESS YOUR EMOTIONS.
T'POL: I DON'T
UNDERSTAND WHY HUMANS
WOULD FEEL COMPELLED
TO FRIGHTEN THEMSELVES.
ARCHER:
GETS THE HEART PUMPING.
T'POL: CARDIOVASCULAR ACTIVITY
WOULD BE MORE EFFICIENT.
ARCHER: YOU NEVER DID GIVE
US YOUR OPINION OF THE MOVIE.
T'POL: THERE WERE
MANY MEDICAL INACCURACIES.
TUCKER: WHAT DID YOU THINK
OF THE STORY?
T'POL: I THOUGHT THE PROTAGONIST
WAS INTERESTING.
TUCKER: DR. FRANKENSTEIN?
T'POL: NO, HIS CREATION.
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE,
THIS WAS THE STORY
OF AN INDIVIDUAL
PERSECUTED BY HUMANS
BECAUSE HE WAS DIFFERENT.
TUCKER: THAT'S ONE WAY
OF LOOKING AT IT.
T'POL: IN MANY WAYS,
THE FILM SEEMED QUITE PROPHETIC.
THE REACTION OF THE VILLAGERS,
FOR EXAMPLE--
IT WAS SIMILAR TO THE RECEPTION
VULCANS RECEIVED
AFTER LANDING ON EARTH.
[ARCHER CHUCKLES]
ARCHER: UH,
I DON'T RECALL ANYONE
GREETING THE VULCAN AMBASSADOR
WITH TORCHES AND PITCHFORKS.
T'POL: NEVERTHELESS, MANY HUMANS
REACTED WITH FEAR AND ANGER.
ARCHER:
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT.
T'POL: I'M GOING TO RECOMMEND
THAT AMBASSADOR SOVAL
WATCH THE FILM.
TUCKER: YOU'RE KIDDING.
T'POL:
I BELIEVE IT WOULD HELP VULCANS
WHO'VE RECENTLY ARRIVED
ON EARTH.
ARCHER: MAYBE INVITING
HER TO MOVIE NIGHT
WASN'T SUCH A GREAT IDEA.
T'POL: ON THE CONTRARY.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
"BRIDE OF FRANKENSTEIN."
HOSHI: Bridge to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
HOSHI: You might want to look
out the window, sir.
[RUMBLING, COMPUTER BEEPS]
REED: THERMAL SHEAR.
SOME OF THOSE ERUPTIONS ARE
GETTING CLOSE TO "ENTERPRISE."
ARCHER: TAKE US UP
ANOTHER 5,000 KILOMETERS.
HELMSMAN: AYE, SIR.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
I'M READING BIO-SIGNS
ON THE PLANET.
TO QUOTE DR. FRANKENSTEIN,
IT'S ALIVE.
ARCHER:
I THOUGHT IT WAS UNINHABITED.
T'POL: IT APPEARS
THAT SEVERAL MICROBIAL SPECIES
WHICH LIVE UNDERGROUND
ARE BEING UNEARTHED
BY THE VOLCANIC ACTIVITY.
ARCHER: SEE WHAT YOU CAN LEARN
ABOUT THEM.
PAUL:
FULL POWER TO THE HULL PLATING.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
NICHOLS: WE'RE BEING HAILED.
PAUL: THIS IS CAPTAIN MAYWEATHER
OF THE E.C.S. "HORIZON."
ALIEN: PREPARE TO SURRENDER
YOUR VESSEL
AND EVACUATE THE CREW.
PAUL: I'LL GIVE YOU OUR CARGO,
BUT NOT OUR SHIP.
ALIEN: YOU WON'T BE HARMED
IF YOU COOPERATE.
DROP OUT OF WARP.
PAUL: WE'RE DOZENS OF
LIGHT-YEARS FROM OUR HOMEWORLD.
THERE HAS TO BE
SOME COMPROMISE WE CAN--
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
TRAVIS:
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
PAUL: BRING THE WEAPON UPGRADES
ONLINE.
STILL THINK YOU CAN
DISABLE THEIR ENGINES?
TRAVIS: IF I CAN GET
A CLEAR SHOT.
BUT I CAN'T DO THAT
AS LONG AS THEY'RE BEHIND US.
[ALARM]
NICHOLS: THEY'VE HIT MODULE 5.
TRAVIS: IT'S GOING TO BE TOUGH
TO MANEUVER
WITH 30 KILOTONS OF CARGO.
WE'VE GOT TO CUT IT LOOSE.
RIANNA: ENGINEERING, STAND BY
TO RELEASE THE PRIMARY CLAMPS.
PAUL: YOU DO REMEMBER
HOW TO FLY THIS SHIP.
TRAVIS:
I'M SURE IT'LL COME BACK TO ME.
PAUL: TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
RELEASE THE CLAMPS.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE CLOSING.
40 METERS. 30.
RIANNA: JUST A FEW MORE CLAMPS.
TRAVIS: 10 METERS.
[ALARM]
RIANNA:
STARBOARD PLATING'S DOWN.
PAUL: TRAVIS!
RIANNA: HULL PLATING'S GONE.
TRAVIS: I'M COMING AROUND AGAIN.
NICHOLS:
THEIR WEAPONS ARE GOING DOWN.
PAUL: KEEP OUR TURRETS
LOCKED ON THEM. OPEN A CHANNEL.
THIS IS CAPTAIN MAYWEATHER.
I'D THINK TWICE BEFORE ATTACKING
ANY OF OUR SHIPS AGAIN.
REDOCK WITH THE CARGO SECTION.
THEN GET US OUT OF HERE.
TRAVIS: AYE, CAPTAIN.
[DOOR BUZZES]
COME IN.
PAUL: ALL PACKED?
TRAVIS: WOULDN'T WANT
TO WEAR OUT MY WELCOME.
PAUL: I GOT A MESSAGE
FROM "ENTERPRISE."
THEY'RE RUNNING AHEAD
OF SCHEDULE.
WE'LL BE DOCKING
IN ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
TRAVIS: IF YOU LIKE, I'LL SPEAK
WITH LIEUTENANT REED.
I'M SURE HE CAN HELP YOU
REMOVE THAT ALIEN BEACON.
PAUL: THANKS.
SO DID YOU EVER MAKE IT
TO TRELKIS III?
TRAVIS: WHAT?
PAUL: TRELKIS III--THE PLANET
WITH THE MULTICENTRIC RINGS.
YOU USED TO TALK ABOUT IT
WHEN WE WERE GROWING UP.
TRAVIS: WE HAVEN'T TRAVELED
QUITE THAT FAR.
PAUL: WELL, WHEN YOU DO...
HOW ABOUT SENDING ME
A SUBSPACE POSTCARD?
TRAVIS: YOU CAN COUNT ON IT.
PAUL: WELL, I'D BETTER GET BACK
TO THE BRIDGE.
SEE YOU IN ANOTHER FOUR YEARS?
TRAVIS: MAYBE SOONER.
PAUL: I'D LIKE THAT.
ARCHER: WELCOME BACK.
TRAVIS: THANK YOU, SIR.
ARCHER: HOW'S YOUR FAMILY?
TRAVIS: THEY'RE OK.
ARCHER: WE SPOTTED SOME DAMAGE
ON THEIR PORT CARGO MODULES.
TRAVIS: PROBABLY AN OLD
METEORITE IMPACT.
ARCHER: YOU SURE
EVERYTHING'S ALL RIGHT?
TRAVIS: NEVER BETTER, SIR.