[CREATURE SQUEAKING]
HOSHI: FEEDING TIME?
PHLOX: WHEN ISN'T IT? HA HA!
HOSHI: WHAT IS THAT?
PHLOX: IT WON'T BITE.
IT'S CALLED A TRIBBLE.
HA HA.
IT WAS EXTREMELY
DIFFICULT TO ACQUIRE.
THEY'RE OUTLAWED ON MOST WORLDS.
HOSHI: WHY? IS IT DANGEROUS?
PHLOX: OH, FAR FROM IT.
ALL IT'S CAPABLE
OF DOING, REALLY,
IS EATING AND BREEDING.
THE PROBLEM IS THEY BREED
QUITE PRODIGIOUSLY.
[SQUEALING]
[CRUNCH, THEN SILENCE]
THE ONLY THING THAT KEEPS
THEIR POPULATION IN CHECK
IS THE ABUNDANCE OF REPTILES
ON THEIR HOMEWORLD.
ARE YOU FEELING
ALL RIGHT, ENSIGN?
HOSHI: I JUST CAME BY TO GIVE
YOU THIS TRANSMISSION.
IT'S FROM
THE DENOBULAN SCIENCE ACADEMY.
MARKED "URGENT."
PHLOX: THANK YOU.
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA
BEND OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
TRAVIS: THESE CAVERNS GO ON
FOR 50 KILOMETERS.
PHLOX:
THEY'VE MAPPED 50 KILOMETERS.
NO ONE KNOWS EXACTLY
HOW FAR THEY EXTEND.
TUCKER: WHAT WERE
THESE SCIENTISTS OF YOURS
DOING DOWN THERE?
PHLOX:
OH, THIS CAVE SYSTEM IS KNOWN
FOR ITS MINERAL FORMATIONS.
THE SPELEOTHEMS ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE PARTICULARLY UNUSUAL.
ARCHER: THEY'VE BEEN UNDERGROUND
FOR SIX MONTHS.
THE DENOBULAN SCIENCE ACADEMY
LOST CONTACT WITH THEM
THREE WEEKS AGO.
THE PLANET'S CALLED XANTORAS.
THE GOVERNMENT'S BEEN
POLITICALLY UNSTABLE
FOR SEVERAL YEARS.
IN THE LAST FEW WEEKS,
A MILITANT FACTION
HAS TAKEN CONTROL.
PHLOX: THEY'RE DEMANDING
THAT ALL OFF-WORLDERS LEAVE.
ANYONE WHO FAILS TO COMPLY
COULD FACE IMPRISONMENT
OR POSSIBLY WORSE.
REED:
THEN WHY DON'T THE DENOBULANS
EVACUATE THEIR OWN SCIENTISTS?
ARCHER:
THEY CAN'T GET HERE IN TIME.
"ENTERPRISE" IS LESS
THAN A DAY AWAY.
WE'VE BEEN ASKED
TO PICK THEM UP.
[BEEPING]
FIRST WE HAVE TO FIND THEM.
YOU'VE HAD
SOME CAVING EXPERIENCE.
TRAVIS: THERE ARE SOME
PRETTY STEEP INCLINES HERE,
BUT I THINK I CAN HANDLE IT.
ARCHER:
WHAT ABOUT YOU AND MALCOLM?
TUCKER: DON'T WORRY, CAPTAIN.
I'M SURE TRAVIS
IS AN EXCELLENT TEACHER.
ARCHER: GET SOME GEAR TOGETHER.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
PHLOX: I REALIZE THIS WAS
AN UNUSUAL REQUEST, CAPTAIN.
I WANT TO THANK YOU.
ARCHER: HAPPY TO HELP, DOCTOR.
TRAVIS: PITONS?
TUCKER: ALL HERE.
TRAVIS: RATION PACKS?
TUCKER: A WEEK'S WORTH.
TRAVIS: FLEX-CABLE?
REED: HMM, 500 METERS.
TRAVIS: WASTE DISPOSAL UNITS?
TUCKER: WHAT ARE THESE FOR?
TRAVIS: WE TAKE OUT EVERYTHING
WE BRING IN.
ARCHER: I JUST SPOKE TO
THE XANTORAS REGIONAL GOVERNOR.
HE'S ISSUED A GENERAL ORDER.
YOU HAVE TO GET THEM
OUT OF THERE IN THREE DAYS.
TUCKER: THAT'S NOT MUCH TIME.
ARCHER: THE MILITARY'S
PREPARING SEARCH PATROLS
TO ARREST
ANY STRAY OFF-WORLDERS
WHEN THE DEADLINE ARRIVES.
IF YOU HAVEN'T FOUND THEM
IN A DAY AND A HALF,
I WANT YOU TO TURN AROUND
AND HEAD BACK.
TUCKER: NO ARGUMENTS HERE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
T'POL: ONE OF THE TRANSPORTS
LEAVING THE PLANET
JUST DECLARED AN EMERGENCY.
HOSHI:
THEIR REACTOR CASING'S RUPTURED.
THE CAPTAIN'S ASKING
THE XANTORANS
FOR PERMISSION TO GO BACK DOWN.
ARCHER:
CAN YOU PUT IT ON SPEAKER?
FEMALE: SEVERAL COMPARTMENTS
HAVE FLOODED WITH RADIATION.
I HAVE INJURED PASSENGERS
AND CREW.
MALE:
YOUR REQUEST HAS BEEN DENIED.
LEAVE ORBIT IMMEDIATELY.
FEMALE: OUR SITUATION
IS CRITICAL!
MALE:
WE'RE TRACKING YOUR VESSEL.
IF YOU ATTEMPT TO LAND,
WE WILL COMMEN--
ARCHER: WHERE ARE THEY?
T'POL: IN A LOW ORBIT,
600 KILOMETERS BELOW US.
ARCHER: SET A COURSE.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
[BEEPING]
I WANT TO SPEAK
TO THEIR CAPTAIN.
PHLOX: THERE COULD BE
INTERNAL BLEEDING.
RUN A HEMOSTATIC SCAN.
[PATIENT SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
PHLOX:
TREAT THESE WITH DERMALINE GEL
AND GIVE HIM TWO CC
OF INAPROVALINE FOR THE PAIN.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
CREWMAN: HE WAS WORKING NEAR
THE REACTOR WHEN IT RUPTURED.
DOCTOR?
PHLOX: GET HIM INTO
THE IMAGING CHAMBER.
[SCANNER WHIRRING]
TUCKER: WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
REED: NOTHING
BUT THREE HUMANS,
ONE OF WHICH IS NOT
ENTIRELY CONVINCED
WE'RE GOING
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
TUCKER: AH, MAKE THAT TWO.
TRAVIS: THIS IS THE NEAREST
ENTRANCE TO THEIR CAMPSITE.
I'D BE WILLING TO BET
THEY CAME THIS WAY.
WATCH YOUR FOOTING.
THERE'S A LOT OF LOOSE ROCK.
TUCKER: THE LAST CAVE I WAS IN
HAD HANDRAILS
AND A GIFT SHOP AND A SNACK BAR.
REED: THERE'S AN OPENING.
OVER HERE.
STILL WILLING TO BET
THEY CAME THIS WAY?
TRAVIS: YES, SIR.
TUCKER: ISN'T THERE A BEGINNERS'
CLIFF WE CAN START ON?
TRAVIS:
DON'T WORRY. I'LL GO FIRST.
ARCHER: HOW'S IT GOING?
PHLOX: THESE TWO ARE DOING WELL.
HIS INJURIES
WERE MORE EXTENSIVE.
HIS BODY ABSORBED A HEAVY
DOSE OF RADIATION.
I'VE STABILIZED HIM FOR NOW,
BUT HE'S GOING TO NEED
INTRACELLULAR REGENERATION.
ARCHER: WHAT ARE HIS CHANCES?
PHLOX: IT'S A COMPLEX PROCEDURE,
BUT I'D SAY THE ODDS
ARE IN HIS FAVOR.
HUDAK: WHERE AM I?
ARCHER: YOU'RE ON MY SHIP,
"ENTERPRISE."
I'M CAPTAIN ARCHER.
HUDAK: WHAT HAPPENED?
ARCHER: THERE WAS
AN ACCIDENT ON YOUR TRANSPORT.
HUDAK: WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
ARCHER: HE'S OUR DOCTOR.
HUDAK: KEEP HIM AWAY FROM ME.
ARCHER: YOU NEED HIS HELP.
HUDAK: I'D RATHER DIE
THAN BE TREATED BY HIM.
PHLOX: OUR TWO SPECIES HAVE
A COMPLICATED HISTORY.
WE'VE GONE TO WAR
WITH THE ANTARANS
ON SEVERAL OCCASIONS.
ARCHER: RECENTLY?
PHLOX: ON THE CONTRARY.
IT'S BEEN 300 YEARS
SINCE OUR LAST CONFLICT.
ARCHER: AND THERE'S STILL
BAD BLOOD BETWEEN YOU?
PHLOX: THEY'VE BEEN
PARTICULARLY BITTER DISPUTES.
ARCHER: IF YOU EXPLAIN TO HIM
THAT HE WON'T SURVIVE
WITHOUT YOUR HELP,
MAYBE HE'D SET THE PAST ASIDE
FOR A FEW HOURS.
PHLOX: I SERIOUSLY DOUBT IT.
HE INSISTED I LEAVE THE ROOM.
I DON'T THINK YOU REALIZE
HOW MUCH "BAD BLOOD" THERE IS.
ARCHER: YOU COULD ALWAYS SEDATE
HIM AND PERFORM THE TREATMENT.
PHLOX:
I HAVE TO RESPECT HIS WISHES.
ARCHER:
EVEN IF HE WISHES TO DIE?
PHLOX: THE WILL OF THE PATIENT
IS THE CORNERSTONE
OF DENOBULAN MEDICAL ETHICS.
ARCHER: DON'T YOU BELIEVE
IF YOU CAN HELP SOMEONE,
YOU'RE ETHICALLY BOUND TO DO SO?
PHLOX:
HIPPOCRATES WASN'T DENOBULAN.
ARCHER:
THIS IS AN EARTH SHIP, DOCTOR.
I WON'T LET THAT MAN
DIE IN MY SICK BAY
IF IT CAN BE PREVENTED.
PHLOX: WITHOUT HIS CONSENT,
THERE IS NOTHING I CAN DO.
ARCHER: I'M GIVING YOU AN ORDER.
PHLOX: I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN...
BUT I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T FOLLOW IT.
[TRAVIS EXHALES]
TRAVIS: WATCH YOUR FOOTING, SIR.
TUCKER: THANKS.
REED: TRAVIS!
TRAVIS: STAY CALM.
COMMANDER, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
TUCKER: JUST TESTING THE ROPE.
TRAVIS: WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE A BREAK?
I'LL SEE WHAT'S BELOW.
REED: HEY. WHAT'S THAT?
TUCKER: I THINK IT'S DENOBULAN.
I'VE SEEN CHARACTERS LIKE THESE
IN PHLOX'S MEDICAL BOOKS.
REED: YOU DON'T
SUPPOSE DENOBULANS
CARRY OUT EVERYTHING
THEY BRING IN?
TUCKER: ROCK SAMPLES.
REED: LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE ON THE RIGHT TRACK.
ARCHER: HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
HUDAK:
I'D LIKE TO RETURN TO MY SHIP.
ARCHER: YOUR SHIP WAS DAMAGED
BY THE REACTOR LEAK.
IT'LL BE A FEW DAYS
BEFORE YOU CAN GO BACK ABOARD.
YOU WERE EXPOSED
TO HIGH LEVELS OF RADIATION.
YOU NEED TREATMENT.
HUDAK: I PREFER TO BE TREATED
BY ANOTHER PHYSICIAN.
ARCHER:
IF YOU DON'T LET PHLOX OPERATE,
YOU WON'T SURVIVE
MORE THAN TWO DAYS.
I UNDERSTAND THERE'S
A TROUBLED HISTORY
BETWEEN YOUR PEOPLES,
BUT I CAN ASSURE YOU
PHLOX IS AN EXCELLENT DOCTOR.
HUDAK: OUR HISTORY IS
MUCH MORE THAN TROUBLED.
DID YOUR DOCTOR TELL YOU
THAT THEIR BATTLE TACTICS
RESULTED IN 20 MILLION
ANTARAN CASUALTIES?
ARCHER: HE WASN'T THAT SPECIFIC.
HUDAK: I IMAGINE NOT.
THEY'VE BEEN VERY SUCCESSFUL
AT PUTTING IT BEHIND THEM.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
ARCHER: DO YOU WANT
TO BECOME A CASUALTY OF A WAR
THAT ENDED 300 YEARS AGO?
PHLOX HAS BEEN
MY CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER
FOR NEARLY TWO YEARS.
I'VE NEVER QUESTIONED HIS SKILL
OR HIS INTEGRITY.
HUDAK: IT'S QUITE POSSIBLE
HE'S A PROFICIENT SURGEON,
BUT I DON'T INTEND TO FIND OUT.
ARCHER: YOU'D RATHER DIE?
HUDAK: I'M THE FIRST ANTARAN
TO EVEN SEE A DENOBULAN
IN SIX GENERATIONS.
ARCHER: IF YOU SPENT
SOME TIME WITH HIM...
IT MIGHT CHANGE
YOUR PERCEPTION OF THEM.
HUDAK: A FEW HOURS
IN OUR HISTORICAL ARCHIVES
MIGHT CHANGE YOURS.
ARCHER:
I PREFER TO MAKE MY JUDGMENTS
BASED ON FIRSTHAND EXPERIENCE.
I RESPECT YOUR HISTORY...
AND THE SACRIFICE
YOUR PEOPLE MADE.
BUT I CAN TELL YOU
THAT THE DENOBULANS
YOU'RE DESCRIBING
ARE NOT THE PEOPLE I'VE MET.
DON'T SACRIFICE YOUR LIFE
BASED ON PRECONCEPTIONS.
WHY HAVEN'T YOU
EVER MENTIONED THIS?
PHLOX:
IT WASN'T OUR PROUDEST MOMENT,
BUT WE'VE DONE OUR BEST
TO PUT IT BEHIND US.
ARCHER: DO YOU KNOW
YOU'RE THE FIRST
DENOBULAN HE'S EVER MET?
PHLOX: AND HE IS THE FIRST
ANTARAN I'VE EVER MET.
ARCHER:
DOESN'T THAT SEEM ODD TO YOU?
THAT IN 300 YEARS,
NEITHER SIDE
HAS TRIED TO RECONCILE.
MAYBE YOU PUT IT
BEHIND YOU TOO QUICKLY.
PHLOX: AS I SAID BEFORE,
THE SITUATION IS COMPLICATED.
FROM CHILDHOOD,
EVERY ANTARAN IS TAUGHT
THAT DENOBULANS ARE ENEMIES
TO BE FEARED, REVILED.
ARCHER: THIS IS YOUR CHANCE
TO PROVE THEM WRONG.
PHLOX: I DOUBT I COULD.
ARCHER: SET ASIDE
YOUR PRECONCEPTIONS.
I MADE SOME HEADWAY WITH HIM,
BUT I WON'T BE THE ONE
HOLDING THE SCALPEL.
SHOW HIM THAT HE CAN TRUST YOU.
PHLOX: DO YOU BELIEVE
I CAN EARN HIS TRUST
IN LESS THAN 36 HOURS?
ARCHER:
ALL I'M ASKING IS THAT YOU TRY.
YOUR ETHICS MIGHT
KEEP YOU FROM TREATING HIM
AGAINST HIS WILL,
BUT NOTHING'S STOPPING YOU
FROM TALKING TO HIM.
YOU'RE A DOCTOR.
HE'S YOUR PATIENT.
FIND A WAY TO HELP HIM.
TUCKER: TOSS A COIN?
REED: THEY WENT THAT WAY.
TUCKER: HOW CAN YOU TELL?
REED: WELL, LOOK AT THOSE.
IF I WAS A GEOLOGIST,
THAT'S THE WAY I'D GO.
TRAVIS:
STAY CLOSE TO THE WALL.
REED:
WELL, I DON'T HAVE MUCH CHOICE.
IT'S GETTING STEEPER.
TRAVIS: LET ME LOCK OFF.
CHECK YOUR SAFETY, COMMANDER.
[REED YELLING]
[TUCKER YELLING]
[TRAVIS GROANING]
[YELLING]
[TRAVIS MOANING]
[TUCKER PANTING]
TRAVIS: I CAN'T REACH IT!
TUCKER: ALMOST.
TRAVIS:
I CAN'T HOLD THIS MUCH LONGER.
TUCKER: STAND BY.
WE'LL TRY AGAIN.
LET'S SWING TOGETHER. YOU READY?
ON 3.
1...
TUCKER: 2...
3!
TRAVIS: THE ROPE'S SLIPPING!
[GROANING]
[TRAVIS PANTING]
TUCKER: WE'RE ALL RIGHT!
TRAVIS: IS IT BROKEN?
TUCKER: YEAH.
YOU TORE A COUPLE
LIGAMENTS, TOO.
TRAVIS: WE NEED TO KEEP MOVING.
JUST GIVE ME SOMETHING
FOR THE PAIN.
TUCKER: SORRY, TRAVIS.
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
TRAVIS: UGH! I CAN MAKE IT, SIR.
REED: WE'RE ALREADY
BEHIND SCHEDULE, ENSIGN.
WE CAN'T HAVE YOU
SLOWING US DOWN.
THANKS FOR GETTING US THIS FAR.
TUCKER: YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
TRAVIS: RESPECTFULLY, SIR,
IT'S NOT ME
THAT I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
[TUCKER CHUCKLES]
TUCKER: GIVE ME SOME LIGHT
ON THIS, MALCOLM.
HUDAK: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
PHLOX: CHECKING YOUR BIO-SIGNS.
NOTHING ELSE.
HUDAK: VERY DILIGENT.
WHAT A DEDICATED
HEALER YOU MUST BE.
PHLOX:
YOU'RE A LONG WAY FROM HOME.
WHAT BROUGHT YOU HERE?
HUDAK:
PRACTICING YOUR BEDSIDE MANNER?
PHLOX:
I ENJOY A GOOD CHALLENGE.
YOU HAVEN'T ANSWERED
MY QUESTION.
HUDAK:
I'M A TEACHER OF XENOMYTHOLOGY.
I STUDY THE LEGENDS
OF ALIEN SPECIES.
PHLOX: WELL, I IMAGINE
THE DIVERSE POPULATION
ON THIS PLANET
MADE IT IDEAL FOR YOUR RESEARCH.
"ENTERPRISE" IS HERE TO PICK UP
THREE DENOBULAN SCIENTISTS.
THEY ALSO FOUND
THIS WORLD UNIQUELY SUITED
TO THEIR FIELDWORK.
HUDAK: HOW DELIGHTFUL THAT
WE HAVE SO MUCH IN COMMON.
HUDAK:
WHY DO YOU WANT TO SAVE MY LIFE?
PHLOX: I'M A DOCTOR.
HUDAK: DO YOU BELIEVE
THAT SAVING ONE ANTARAN
WILL ASSUAGE YOUR GUILT
FOR KILLING MILLIONS?
PHLOX: I HAVEN'T KILLED ANYONE.
HUDAK: NOW YOU FINALLY
HAVE YOUR CHANCE.
PHLOX: I ASSURE YOU,
THE REGENERATION PROCEDURE
IS QUITE SAFE.
IF YOU'LL ALLOW ME TO PROCEED...
HUDAK: YOU MUST KNOW A GREAT
DEAL ABOUT OUR ANATOMY
AFTER WHAT YOUR DOCTORS
DID TO US.
TELL ME, WERE YOU RAISED
LISTENING TO STORIES
ABOUT MY PEOPLE,
THE EVIL ANTARANS?
DID THEY GIVE YOU NIGHTMARES?
PHLOX: I COULD ASK YOU THE SAME
QUESTION ABOUT MY PEOPLE.
HUDAK:
DO YOU HAVE CHILDREN, DOCTOR?
PHLOX: WHY?
HUDAK: DID YOU TELL
THOSE STORIES TO THEM?
DID YOU TEACH THEM
TO HATE ANTARANS
JUST LIKE YOU WERE TAUGHT?
PHLOX: MY CHILDREN HAVE NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS.
HUDAK: DON'T THEY?
IF THEY WERE HERE RIGHT NOW,
WHAT WOULD THEY THINK
ABOUT THEIR FATHER
TALKING TO AN ANTARAN?
PHLOX: ENOUGH.
WOULD YOU EVEN LET THEM
IN THE SAME ROOM WITH ME?
PHLOX: I HAVE TRIED TO
TREAT YOU WITH RESPECT,
BUT I REFUSE TO LISTEN
TO THESE INSULTS.
YOU'RE THE REASON
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO PUT THE PAST BEHIND US.
YOU HAVE KEPT THIS HATRED ALIVE.
NO DENOBULAN WOULD WANT
TO BE IN THE SAME ROOM WITH YOU.
T'POL: MAY I JOIN YOU?
PHLOX: ACTUALLY,
I'M NOT IN THE MOOD
FOR COMPANY, SUB-COMMANDER.
WAIT. I'M SORRY. SIT DOWN.
T'POL: IF YOU WISH TO BE ALONE--
PHLOX: SIT. PLEASE. PLEASE.
[PHLOX CLEARS THROAT]
HOW ARE THE, UH, REPAIRS
TO THE TRANSPORT COMING?
T'POL: SLOWLY.
THE DAMAGE WAS EXTENSIVE.
HOW IS YOUR PATIENT?
PHLOX: DYING.
BUT, UH, THAT SEEMS TO BE
HIS WISH.
T'POL: THAT'S UNFORTUNATE.
PHLOX: I'VE HAD PATIENTS
REFUSE TREATMENT BEFORE,
BUT, UH, USUALLY IN
THE FINAL STAGES OF AN ILLNESS.
BUT THIS MAN SEEMS
DETERMINED TO DIE
JUST TO PROVE A POINT.
IT'S PAINFUL TO ADMIT,
BUT I UNDERSTAND WHY.
WHEN I WAS QUITE YOUNG,
I WANTED TO TAKE A TRIP
TO AN ARBOREAL PLANET
NEAR OUR SYSTEM.
IT WAS A PARK OF SORTS
WITH A GREAT VARIETY
OF EXOTIC ANIMAL LIFE.
SOME FRIENDS AND I HAD PLANNED
THE JOURNEY FOR MONTHS,
BUT, UH, THE WEEK BEFORE
I WAS SUPPOSED TO LEAVE,
ONE OF MY GRANDMOTHERS
TOOK ME ASIDE
AND TOLD ME I COULDN'T GO.
T'POL: WHY NOT?
PHLOX:
SHE SAID THE PLANET WAS TAINTED.
ANTARANS HAD LIVED THERE ONCE.
EVEN THOUGH THEY'D
BEEN GONE FOR YEARS,
SHE BELIEVED THE PLACE
HAD BEEN SPOILED
BY THEIR PRESENCE.
T'POL: DID YOU GO?
PHLOX: NO.
BUT WHEN I HAD CHILDREN OF
MY OWN, I TOOK THEM THERE.
I WAS DETERMINED NOT TO RAISE
THEM AS I WAS RAISED.
T'POL: YOUR CHILDREN
WERE FORTUNATE TO HAVE A FATHER
WHO TAUGHT THEM TO
EMBRACE OTHER CULTURES.
PHLOX: I CERTAINLY TRIED.
T'POL: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
PHLOX: THANKS FOR YOUR COMPANY.
GOOD NIGHT.
TUCKER: CAN YOU SEE ANYTHING?
[REED GRUNTS]
REED: MORE OF THE SAME.
TUCKER: ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS THE WAY THEY CAME?
REED:
I DIDN'T SEE ANY OTHER PASSAGE.
ARCHER:
WE'LL GIVE IT ANOTHER HALF-HOUR,
AND THEN WE'RE TURNING BACK.
[SCANNER BEEPING]
REED: THREE BIO-SIGNS--
DENOBULAN.
TUCKER: HOW FAR?
REED: ABOUT 50 METERS.
YOLEN: WHO ARE YOU?
TUCKER: COMMANDER TUCKER OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
THIS IS LIEUTENANT REED.
YOLEN:
I HOPE YOU WON'T THINK I'M RUDE,
BUT THERE ARE MANY OTHER
CAVERNS HERE TO EXPLORE.
TUCKER: WE'RE NOT GEOLOGISTS.
REED: THE DENOBULAN SCIENCE
ACADEMY ASKED US TO FIND YOU.
YOLEN: WHY?
TUCKER:
THE XANTORANS, THEY'VE GIVEN
ALL THE OFF-WORLDERS
3 DAYS TO LEAVE,
AND THAT WAS TWO DAYS AGO.
ZEPHT: THEN YOU'D BETTER HURRY.
TUCKER: YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WE'VE BEEN ORDERED
TO TAKE YOU OUT OF HERE.
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF HARD
CLIMBING AHEAD OF US,
SO YOU'D BETTER DECIDE
HOW MUCH OF THIS GEAR
YOU CAN DO WITHOUT.
YOLEN: WE'RE SORRY YOU CAME
ALL THIS WAY,
BUT WE'RE NOT LEAVING.
TUCKER:
WE'RE NOT LEAVING WITHOUT YOU.
YOLEN: YOU'VE WARNED US
ABOUT THE SITUATION, COMMANDER.
YOU'VE ACCOMPLISHED
YOUR MISSION.
REED: NOT QUITE.
YOUR SCIENCE ACADEMY
WILL HOLD US RESPONSIBLE
IF WE COME BACK ALONE.
TREVIX: IF THE ACADEMY KNEW
THE PROGRESS WE WERE MAKING,
THEY'D NEVER HAVE SENT YOU.
TUCKER: YOU DON'T GET IT.
WHEN THE XANTORANS
GET THEIR HANDS ON YOU,
THEY'LL THROW YOU IN PRISON.
THEY MAY EVEN EXECUTE YOU.
YOLEN: ALL THE MORE REASON
FOR US TO STAY DOWN HERE
WHERE WE'RE SAFE.
REED: YOU CAN'T STAY
HERE FOREVER.
ZEPHT: I DOUBT WE'LL NEED TO.
THE GOVERNMENT CHANGES
HANDS SO OFTEN,
EVERYTHING WILL PROBABLY
BE CLEARED UP
BY THE TIME WE'RE FINISHED.
TUCKER: I REALIZE YOUR WORK
IS IMPORTANT,
BUT YOU CAN'T RISK
YOUR LIVES FOR THESE ROCKS.
YOLEN: ROCKS?
THIS IS THE MOST REMARKABLE
COLLECTION OF SPELEOTHEMS
WE'VE EVER SEEN.
THERE'S CALCITE, ARAGONITE,
BOTYROIDAL FLOWSTONE.
I'VE SPENT 14 YEARS SEARCHING
FOR TRACTOSITES THIS PERFECT.
THESE SAMPLES
COULD PROVIDE CLUES
TO PREVENT SEISMIC DISASTERS
ON DENOBULA.
TUCKER:
HOW MUCH LONGER DO YOU NEED?
TREVIX: TWO WEEKS, MAYBE THREE.
TUCKER: THREE WEEKS?
I'VE SPENT THE LAST
TWO DAYS FALLING DOWN CLIFFS
AND GETTING STUCK IN LAVA TUBES
ALL JUST TO FIND YOU.
NOW, I'VE GOT AN INJURED MAN
WAITING FOR US.
AND WE HAVE JUST ENOUGH TIME
TO GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE WE END UP IN FRONT
OF A XANTORAS FIRING SQUAD.
MY ORDERS ARE TO BRING YOU BACK.
AND I PROMISE YOU,
THAT'S WHAT I'M GOING TO DO.
YOLEN:
YOU CAN'T FORCE US TO LEAVE.
TUCKER: WANT TO BET?
WE DIDN'T RISK OUR LIVES
JUST TO HEAR YOU SAY,
"THANKS, BUT NO THANKS."
SO PACK UP WHATEVER YOU NEED
BECAUSE I SWEAR,
I'LL TIE YOU UP
AND DRAG YOU OUT BY YOUR ANKLES
IF THAT'S HOW YOU WANT IT.
YOLEN: WE HAVE A LOT OF SAMPLES.
WE'LL NEED YOUR HELP.
ARCHER: FINE.
HUDAK: I'D PREFER TO SPEND
MY LAST FEW DAYS ALONE.
PHLOX: THAT'S YOUR DECISION,
BUT IF MY KNOWLEDGE
OF ANTARAN LIFE-SPANS
IS CORRECT,
YOUR LAST DAYS WON'T COME
FOR ABOUT 60 YEARS.
HUDAK:
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
PHLOX: ONCE THE INTRACELLULAR
REGENERATION IS COMPLETE,
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO--
HUDAK: I REFUSED YOUR TREATMENT.
PHLOX: I NEED TO TAKE YOU
OFF THE PAIN MEDICATION
BEFORE I BEGIN THE PROCEDURE.
HUDAK: GET AWAY FROM ME.
I WAS TOLD YOUR PRINCIPLES
PREVENTED YOU FROM TREATING ME
AGAINST MY WILL.
OR DON'T YOUR ETHICS
APPLY TO ANTARANS?
PHLOX: I DID HAVE NIGHTMARES.
HUDAK: WHAT?
PHLOX: YOU ASKED ME
IF I HAD HEARD STORIES
AS A CHILD ABOUT THE ANTARANS.
MY GRANDMOTHER LIVED
THROUGH THE LAST WAR.
I WOULD LAY IN MY BED AT NIGHT
THINKING ABOUT HER STORIES,
TERRIFIED THAT ONE
OF THOSE EVIL ANTARANS
WOULD CLIMB THROUGH MY WINDOW.
HUDAK: I HOPE YOUR CONFESSION
MAKES YOU FEEL BETTER, DOCTOR,
BUT IT DOESN'T CHANGE A THING.
PHLOX: YOU ALSO ASKED ME
IF I HAVE CHILDREN.
I HAVE FIVE.
AND, NO, I NEVER TOLD THEM
MY GRANDMOTHER'S STORIES.
WHEN THEY ASKED ME
ABOUT THE ANTARANS,
I TOLD THEM THE TRUTH,
AS BEST AS I KNEW IT.
I TOLD THEM
ABOUT OUR MILITARY CAMPAIGNS
AGAINST YOUR PEOPLE,
ABOUT HOW WE HAD DEMONIZED YOU,
TURNED YOU
INTO A FACELESS ENEMY.
I WANTED THEM
TO LEARN TO JUDGE PEOPLE
FOR WHAT THEY REALLY ARE,
NOT WHAT
THE PROPAGANDA TELLS THEM.
HUDAK: HOW WOULD YOU KNOW
WHO WE REALLY ARE?
PHLOX: I DON'T.
BUT I AM PROUD TO SAY
THAT MY CHILDREN WOULD CONSIDER
MY GRANDMOTHER'S ATTITUDE
ARCHAIC.
ALL OF THEM BUT ONE.
WE HAVE GROWN MORE OPEN-MINDED
SINCE THE LAST WAR,
BUT THERE ARE STILL DENOBULANS
WHO FEAR ANTARANS,
EVEN HATE THEM.
MY YOUNGEST SON, METTUS,
WAS SEDUCED BY THOSE PEOPLE.
I DID MY BEST
TO CONVINCE HIM HE WAS MISTAKEN.
I TOLD HIM I WOULDN'T TOLERATE
THE VALUES HE WAS EMBRACING.
IT CREATED A RIFT BETWEEN US.
MAYBE I DIDN'T DO ENOUGH
TO REACH HIM.
THE LAST TIME WE SPOKE
WAS NEARLY 10 YEARS AGO.
YOU WANTED TO KNOW
WHAT MY CHILDREN WOULD THINK
IF THEY WERE HERE NOW.
I CAN TELL YOU
WHAT METTUS WOULD THINK.
HE WOULD BE HAPPY
TO HAVE ME GRANT YOUR REQUEST
AND LET YOU DIE.
BUT THAT IS NOT THE EXAMPLE
I TRIED TO SET FOR MY CHILDREN.
WHY NOT LIVE?
SET AN EXAMPLE FOR YOURS.
TUCKER: WHAT'S WRONG?
YOLEN: NOTHING.
TUCKER: THEN KEEP MOVING.
REED: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?!
TUCKER: I DON'T KNOW.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
YOLEN: I JUST NEED A MOMENT.
TUCKER: WE DON'T HAVE A MOMENT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING UP THERE?
ARE THOSE ROCK SAMPLES?
WE CAN'T CARRY ANY MORE.
YOLEN: IT TOOK US SIX WEEKS
TO EXTRACT THESE
FROM THE ROCK BED.
TUCKER: IF YOU DON'T START
MOVING IN THE NEXT 5 SECONDS,
I'M GONNA TAKE MY PHASE PISTOL
AND SHOOT YOU IN THE ASS!
YOLEN: THESE ARE PRICELESS!
TUCKER: 1, 2...
[RUMBLING]
GO!
COULD BE SOME KIND
OF SEISMIC ACTIVITY.
REED:
FEELS LIKE WEAPONS FIRE TO ME.
PRETTY HIGH YIELD
BY THE SOUND OF IT.
TUCKER: WE'VE STILL GOT 2 HOURS
UNTIL THE DEADLINE.
YOU BETTER GET
YOUR CLIMBING GEAR ON.
YOLEN: WE DON'T HAVE ANY
CLIMBING GEAR.
REED: YOU MEAN TO TELL US
THAT YOU CLIMBED DOWN
THAT ROCK FACE
WITHOUT ANY ROPES,
ANY SAFETY EQUIPMENT AT ALL?
YOLEN: EXACTLY.
TUCKER:
WELL, IN THAT CASE, AFTER YOU.
[RUMBLING]
TUCKER: GET AGAINST THE WALL!
[COUGHING]
TUCKER: EVERYONE ALL RIGHT?
REED: I'M FINE.
TREVIX: YES.
TUCKER: LET'S KEEP MOVING
BEFORE WE GET TRAPPED DOWN HERE.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
HOSHI: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: IS THAT THE GOVERNOR?
HOSHI:
HE SAYS HIS TIME IS PRECIOUS.
ARCHER: SO IS MINE.
GOVERNOR: CAPTAIN ARCHER, I
THOUGHT I MADE MYSELF CLEAR.
ARCHER: YOU DID.
WHICH MAKES ME WONDER
WHY YOU'RE ATTACKING MY PEOPLE.
GOVERNOR: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
ARCHER: ONE OF YOUR PATROLS
HAS OPENED FIRE
IN THE VICINITY OF THE CAVES.
YOUR GENERAL ORDER
DOESN'T GO INTO EFFECT
FOR ANOTHER HOUR AND A HALF.
GOVERNOR: I ASSURE YOU,
THEY'RE NOT TARGETING
YOUR CREWMEN OR THE DENOBULANS.
ARCHER:
THEN WHO ARE THEY SHOOTING AT?
GOVERNOR: SOLDIERS
FROM THE PREVIOUS REGIME.
THEY'VE REFUSED TO ACCEPT
THE SHIFT IN POWER.
ARCHER:
THAT'S NOT MY CONCERN.
YOU'RE ENDANGERING MY PEOPLE.
YOU'VE GOT TO WAIT
UNTIL THEY'RE IN THE CLEAR.
GOVERNOR:
I'M AFRAID THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
ARCHER:
IT'S WHAT WE AGREED TO.
GOVERNOR: WE AGREED TO GIVE
YOU 3 DAYS, NOTHING MORE.
ARCHER: TARGET THE PATROL
THAT'S FIRING AT THOSE CAVES.
GOVERNOR: IF YOU ATTACK US,
WE'LL RETALIATE.
T'POL: WE'RE LOCKED ON
TO THE COORDINATES.
ARCHER: CHARGE WEAPONS.
GOVERNOR: DO YOU REALLY WANT TO
BE AT WAR WITH US, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: THE QUESTION IS, DO YOU
WANT TO BE AT WAR WITH US?
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE GOT
YOUR HANDS FULL ALREADY.
STICK TO OUR ORIGINAL AGREEMENT
AND YOU WON'T FIND YOURSELF
FIGHTING ON TWO FRONTS.
[DISTANT BOOMS]
YOLEN: COMMANDER, THE BOMBING
SEEMS TO HAVE STOPPED.
REED: WE NEED TO GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE IT STARTS UP AGAIN.
PHLOX: YOU WANTED TO SEE ME?
HUDAK: WHAT YOU SAID
ABOUT YOUR SON--
YOU SEEM SINCERE IN YOUR DESIRE
TO SET AN EXAMPLE
FOR YOUR CHILDREN.
I WISH MORE DENOBULANS
FELT THAT WAY.
PHLOX: MANY DO.
PERHAPS IF YOU MET
MORE OF US...
HUDAK: THAT SEEMS UNLIKELY.
PHLOX: IS THAT ALL YOU WANTED
TO SAY TO ME?
HUDAK: YOU MADE ME THINK
ABOUT MY OWN FAMILY.
I HAVE CHILDREN, AS WELL.
I'VE DECIDED TO ACCEPT
YOUR TREATMENT.
YOLEN: MY SPELEOTHEMS!
TUCKER: FORGET ABOUT THEM.
YOLEN: FORTUNATELY, I HAVE
SOME OTHER SAMPLES IN MY CASE.
ARCHER: TRY THEM AGAIN.
HOSHI:
ENTERPRISE TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
PLEASE RESPOND.
ARCHER: PREP SHUTTLEPOD 1.
HAVE A SECURITY TEAM MEET ME
IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
THE XANTORANS HAVE MOBILIZED
THEIR MILITARY PATROLS.
THEY'LL DETECT A SHUTTLE LAUNCH.
ARCHER: NOTED.
TUCKER: Tucker to "Enterprise."
ARCHER: YOU'RE CUTTING IT
PRETTY CLOSE, TRIP.
THE DEADLINE PASSED
TWO HOURS AGO.
TUCKER: BETTER LATE THAN NEVER.
ARCHER: THE DENOBULANS?
TUCKER: ALL ABOARD,
ALONG WITH SOME VERY RARE
SPELEOTHEMS.
T'POL:
CAPTAIN, THERE'S A SMALL CRAFT
CLOSING ON THE SHUTTLEPOD.
IT'S A PATROL SHIP.
ARCHER: YOU'VE
GOT COMPANY, TRIP.
REED: I SEE THEM.
BEARING 184 MARK 27.
MINIMAL DAMAGE.
THEY'RE USING LOW-POWER
PARTICLE BEAMS.
ARCHER: DO YOU NEED ASSISTANCE?
TUCKER: Stand by.
I THINK THEY'RE JUST TRYING
TO GIVE US A LITTLE KICK
IN THE PANTS.
ARCHER: HOW IS HE?
PHLOX: HE'LL BE A BIT GROGGY
WHEN HE COMES OUT
OF THE ANESTHESIA.
BUT THE PROCEDURE
WAS SUCCESSFUL.
ARCHER: I'M GLAD YOU DIDN'T
DEFY MY ORDERS.
I WASN'T LOOKING FORWARD
TO THROWING YOU IN IRONS.
PHLOX: NEITHER WAS I.
ARCHER:
HOW DID YOU CONVINCE HIM?
PHLOX: YOU MUST BE
FAMILIAR WITH THE PRINCIPLE
OF DOCTOR/PATIENT
CONFIDENTIALITY.
OF COURSE, YOU COULD
ALWAYS ORDER ME TO TELL YOU.
ARCHER: DR. PHLOX WANTED
TO SEE YOU OFF,
BUT HE'S BUSY TREATING
ONE OF MY CREWMEN
WHO WAS INJURED ON THE SURFACE.
HUDAK:
THAT'S ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
THE DOCTOR AND I SPENT MORE
THAN ENOUGH TIME TOGETHER.
ARCHER:
IT'S TOO BAD YOUR RESEARCH
ON XANTORAS WAS CUT SHORT.
HUDAK: THE TIME I SPENT ON YOUR
SHIP WAS AN EDUCATION IN ITSELF.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
ARCHER: YOU DO KNOW WE CAME HERE
TO RESCUE THREE DENOBULAN
GEOLOGISTS?
HUDAK: PHLOX TOLD ME.
ARCHER: I UNDERSTAND THEY'LL BE
HEADING HOME ON YOUR TRANSPORT.
I HOPE THAT WON'T BE A PROBLEM.
HUDAK: HAVE THEY BEEN INFORMED
THAT I'LL BE TRAVELING
WITH THEM?
ARCHER: I HAD A TALK WITH THEM.
HUDAK:
AND WHAT WAS THEIR RESPONSE?
ARCHER: THEY'RE WILLING
IF YOU ARE.
PHLOX:
COMPUTER, BEGIN RECORDING.
DEAR METTUS, I KNOW IT'S BEEN
SOME TIME SINCE I'VE WRITTEN,
AND I KNOW CHANCES ARE SLIM THAT
YOU'LL RESPOND TO THIS LETTER.
HOWEVER, SOMETHING HAS HAPPENED
THAT COMPELS ME TO TRY
TO REACH YOU AGAIN.
I'VE HAD AN EXPERIENCE
THAT HAS OPENED MANY OLD WOUNDS.
AS PAINFUL AS IT'S BEEN,
IT'S ALSO CHANGED
SOMETHING IN ME.
I HOPE, IF YOU'RE
WILLING TO LISTEN,
IT MIGHT BEGIN TO CHANGE
SOMETHING IN YOU.