T'POL: IT'S LOSING MASS
AT AN EXTRAORDINARY RATE.
REED: HOW LONG BEFORE
IT GOES SUPERNOVA?
T'POL:
A HUNDRED YEARS, MAYBE 200.
ARCHER:
TOO BAD WE WON'T BE AROUND.
IT'S GONNA BE
ONE HELL OF AN EXPLOSION.
T'POL: SPEAK FOR YOURSELF.
I MIGHT VERY WELL BE AROUND.
TUCKER: CAN'T FORGET
VULCAN LONGEVITY, CAPTAIN.
A HUNDRED YEARS FROM NOW?
HOW OLD WOULD THAT MAKE YOU?
ARCHER: NO EARTH SHIP HAS
EVER BEEN WITHIN 10 LIGHT-YEARS
OF A HYPERGIANT.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
HOW MUCH FARTHER CAN WE MOVE IN?
T'POL: OUR HULL TEMPERATURE
IS APPROACHING 1,100 DEGREES.
IT WOULD BE UNSAFE
TO GET ANY CLOSER.
ARCHER: THEN WE'LL HAVE
TO RUN OUR SCANS FROM HERE.
TELL ASTROMETRICS TO GET GOING.
I'M SURE THEY'RE
CHAMPING AT THE BIT.
[BEEPING]
REED: WE MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO GET ANY CLOSER,
BUT SOMEONE ELSE HAS.
ARCHER: YOU FOUND A SHIP?
REED: BEARING 261 MARK 4.
THEY MUST BE AT LEAST
20,000 KILOMETERS
FARTHER IN THAN WE ARE.
ARCHER: LET'S SEE HER.
RECOGNIZE IT?
T'POL: NO.
ARCHER: HAIL THEM.
HOSHI: THE INTERFERENCE
IS PRETTY HEAVY, SIR.
ARCHER: THEN TRY AUDIO.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
I ASSUME YOU'VE DETECTED US.
DRENNIK: Captain Drennik.
Where have you traveled from?
ARCHER:
THE SOL SYSTEM. AND YOU?
DRENNIK: We come
from a system called Vissia,
more than
25 light-years from here.
We saw you arrive yesterday.
I assume you're here
to study the hypergiant.
ARCHER: MY SPECIES
HAS NEVER SEEN ONE UP CLOSE.
DRENNIK: It is quite a sight.
Have you measured its rate
of nucleosynthesis?
ARCHER: I'M AFRAID
WE HAVEN'T DEVELOPED
THE TECHNOLOGY TO DO THAT.
DRENNIK: If you
don't mind eliminating
the development stage,
I'd be more than happy to help
you modify your sensors.
ARCHER: THANK YOU.
I'M NOT SURE WE HAVE ANYTHING
TO OFFER YOU IN RETURN.
DRENNIK: You could invite
us to visit your ship.
Meeting new species is
one of our primary goals.
ARCHER: IT'S ONE OF OURS,
AS WELL.
WE'D BE HONORED TO HAVE YOU
JOIN US FOR DINNER.
DRENNIK:
We'll be there within the hour.
I look forward to it.
TUCKER: IT'LL BE NICE
TO HAVE A FIRST CONTACT
WHERE NO ONE'S THINKING
ABOUT CHARGING WEAPONS.
ARCHER: HMM.
TELL CHEF WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE SOME VISITORS.
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
DRENNIK: TRINESIUM
CAN WITHSTAND TEMPERATURES
UP TO 18,000 DEGREES.
WE'VE BEEN USING IT
TO CONSTRUCT OUR HULLS
FOR OVER A CENTURY.
ARCHER: YOU MUST BE ABLE TO GET
DOWN INTO THE PHOTOSPHERE
OF MOST G-TYPE STARS.
DRENNIK: WE CAN GET EVEN DEEPER
WITH OUR STRATOPOD.
IT'S GOT TWICE THE SHIELDING.
ARCHER: FLYING INTO STARS
IS A LONG WAY OFF FOR US.
DRENNIK: YOUR TECHNOLOGY
WILL EVOLVE.
WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS
THAT YOU'RE EXPLORERS.
ARCHER: WE HAVE GONE FARTHER
THAN ANY OTHER HUMANS.
DRENNIK: YOU MIGHT ENJOY
GOING EVEN FARTHER.
I'M TAKING THE STRATOPOD
INTO THE HYDROGEN LAYER
TOMORROW.
I'D BE PLEASED
TO HAVE YOU JOIN ME.
ARCHER: I AM AN EXPLORER.
TUCKER: THIS IS CALLED VANILLA,
AND THIS IS CHOCOLATE.
GIVE IT A TRY.
OH, NO. WAIT.
YOU'VE GOT TO EAT
THE CHERRY FIRST. THIS.
TRAISTANA: WHY?
TUCKER: AH, YOU JUST DO.
VEYLO: A HUMAN TRADITION?
TUCKER: EXACTLY.
REED: AREN'T YOU
GOING TO INTRODUCE ME?
TUCKER: AH, THIS IS
MALCOLM REED,
OUR ARMORY OFFICER.
THIS IS TRAISTANA,
A XENOBIOLOGIST,
AND VEYLO IS A TACTICAL OFFICER.
REED: VERY PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
TUCKER: WHY DON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
THE CAPTAIN DID ASK US
TO MINGLE.
REED: INDEED.
I WAS JUST SPEAKING
WITH THEIR CHIEF ENGINEER
AND HIS WIFE.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD SAY HELLO.
TUCKER: SEE YOU LATER.
I'M TOLD YOU'RE
THE CHIEF ENGINEER.
ENGINEER: COMMANDER TUCKER.
LIEUTENANT REED POINTED YOU OUT.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
TUCKER: THANK YOU.
THIS IS MY WIFE, CALLA.
CALLA:
I'M GLAD YOU INVITED US HERE.
TUCKER: ARE YOU ENJOYING
YOUR FOOD?
CALLA: OH, VERY MUCH.
ENGINEER: I HOPE YOU GET
THE CHANCE TO SAMPLE OUR FOOD.
IT'S MORE FRAGRANT THAN YOURS.
TUCKER: I LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
I'D ALSO LIKE TO GET A PEEK
AT YOUR ENGINE ROOM.
ENGINEER: BY ALL MEANS.
TUCKER: TRIP TUCKER.
WELCOME ABOARD.
COGENITOR: HELLO.
CALLA: IT HAS NO NAME.
IT'S OUR COGENITOR.
TUCKER: COGENITOR?
CALLA:
WE'RE HOPING TO HAVE A BABY.
TUCKER: AH.
ENGINEER: OUR WARP CORE
EMITS OMICRON RADIATION.
I RECOMMEND YOU SPEAK
WITH YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT AN INOCULATION.
TUCKER: SURE THING.
PHLOX: THIS SHOULD DO IT.
TUCKER: SO YOU'VE HEARD
OF THESE COGENITORS.
PHLOX: NOT ALL SPECIES
ARE LIMITED TO TWO SEXES.
IN FACT, I, UH,
HAVE IT ON GOOD AUTHORITY
THAT THE RIGELIANS HAVE FOUR,
OR WAS IT FIVE?
TUCKER: SO YOU'RE SAYING THAT
THIS MAN OR WOMAN OR WHATEVER
IS A THIRD SEX?
PHLOX:
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I'M SAYING.
TUCKER: AND SHE...
IT--IS PART
OF THE IMPREGNATION PROCESS.
PHLOX: PRECISELY.
I'M PRETTY FAMILIAR WITH
HOW IT WORKS WITH TWO SEXES,
BUT...
PHLOX: MULTI-GENDER TECHNIQUES
AREN'T ALWAYS THE SAME,
BUT IN THIS CASE, I IMAGINE
THE COGENITOR PROVIDES
AN ENZYME,
WHICH FACILITATES CONCEPTION.
TUCKER:
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY "PROVIDES"?
PHLOX: WELL, FIRST,
THE FEMALE HAS TO--
TUCKER:
NO. NO, NO, NO, DON'T TELL ME.
I DON'T THINK I WANT TO KNOW.
PHLOX: OH, WELL. MM!
I HAVE PICTURES.
TUCKER: UH, I THINK I'LL PASS.
SO, HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA LAST?
I MIGHT WANT TO STAY THERE
FOR A WHILE.
PHLOX: IT SHOULD PROTECT YOU
FROM OMICRON RADIATION
FOR ABOUT, UH, 12 YEARS.
TUCKER: THAT SHOULD BE ENOUGH.
THANKS, DOC.
PHLOX: KEEP AN OPEN MIND,
COMMANDER, HMM?
YOU CAME ON THIS MISSION
TO MEET OTHER SPECIES,
NO MATTER HOW MANY GENDERS
THEY MAY HAVE.
DRENNIK: THERE ARE MORE
THINGS IN HEAVEN AND EARTH
THAN ARE DREAMT OF
IN YOUR PHILOSOPHY.
ARCHER:
WHERE'D YOU HEAR THAT?
DRENNIK:
"HAMLET," ACT ONE, SCENE FIVE.
YOUR COMMUNICATIONS
OFFICER WAS KIND ENOUGH
TO PROVIDE US WITH SOME
OF YOUR LITERATURE.
I ASSUMED YOU APPROVED.
ARCHER: ABSOLUTELY,
BUT I DIDN'T THINK YOU'D
BE QUOTING IT THE NEXT DAY.
DRENNIK:
WE RETAIN MOST OF WHAT WE READ.
ARCHER: AND YOU OBVIOUSLY READ
PRETTY QUICKLY.
DRENNIK: AFTER I FINISHED
SHAKESPEARE LAST NIGHT,
I BEGAN READING
THE PLAYS OF SOPHOCLES.
WHAT DO YOU RECOMMEND
AFTER THAT?
ARCHER: SEEMS LIKE YOU'RE
PICKING
THE GOOD ONES ALL BY YOURSELF.
THAT'S GOT TO BE
IONIZED HYDROGEN.
DRENNIK: IT'S GENERATING
MAGNETIC CURRENTS.
ARCHER:
I'VE GOT FRIENDS BACK AT HOME
WHO ARE NOT GOING TO
BELIEVE THIS.
DRENNIK: I HAVE FRIENDS
WHO'LL BE EQUALLY IMPRESSED
WITH "MACBETH."
WE'RE ALMOST
INTO THE CHROMOSPHERE.
ENGINEER: THE ANTIMATTER STREAM
IS COMPRESSED
BEFORE THE DEUTERIUM'S
INJECTED INTO THE CORE.
TUCKER: SO YOU DON'T NEED
MAGNETIC CONFINEMENT.
ENGINEER:
LET ME BRING UP THE SCHEMATICS.
TUCKER:
WHERE WE COME FROM, EARTH--
THERE ARE ONLY TWO GENDERS.
ENGINEER:
THAT'S TRUE OF MOST WORLDS.
TUCKER:
I DON'T MEAN TO PRY, BUT...
DOES EVERY FAMILY
HAVE A COGENITOR?
ENGINEER:
THAT WOULDN'T BE VERY EFFICIENT.
THEY ARE ONLY NEEDED
WHEN A COUPLE'S TRYING
TO HAVE A CHILD.
TUCKER: OH.
AND WHEN THEY'RE NOT?
ENGINEER: THE COGENITOR
IS ASSIGNED TO ANOTHER COUPLE.
THEY MAKE UP ABOUT 3%
OF OUR POPULATION,
WHICH SEEMS TO BE
A PERFECT RATIO.
NATURE HAS A WAY
OF FINDING THE RIGHT BALANCE.
TUCKER: IS THE ONE I MET
THE ONLY ONE ON YOUR SHIP?
ENGINEER: THE ONLY ONE.
ONCE CALLA AND I
ARE FINISHED WITH IT,
I DOUBT IT'LL BE NEEDED
BEFORE WE RETURN HOME.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO TAKE
A CLOSER LOOK
AT THE PLASMA CONVERTERS?
TUCKER: I WOULD. THANKS.
SO DOES IT LIVE
WITH YOU AND YOUR WIFE?
ENGINEER:
WE KEEP IT IN OUR QUARTERS, YES.
TUCKER: WHAT DOES IT DO
WHEN YOU'RE NOT...
ENGINEER: IT EATS, SLEEPS.
THERE'S NOT MUCH ELSE
FOR IT TO DO.
TUCKER: WHAT ABOUT SCHOOL?
ENGINEER:
THEY ONLY SERVE ONE PURPOSE.
SENDING THEM TO SCHOOL
WOULD MAKE NO SENSE.
WHY ARE YOU
SO CURIOUS ABOUT THEM?
TUCKER: HUMANS ARE VERY CURIOUS.
ENGINEER: HMM.
YOU MIGHT FIND
THIS DIFFICULT TO BELIEVE,
BUT THIS POLYMER
IS COMPOSED OF OVER 200
NATURALLY OCCURRING ELEMENTS.
TUCKER: THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
ENGINEER:
I READ IN YOUR DATABASE
THAT YOU'VE DISCOVERED ONLY 92.
I UNDERSTAND HOW THIS
MIGHT SEEM UNNERVING.
TUCKER:
A LOT OF THINGS AROUND HERE DO,
BUT, UH, I'M TRYING
TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND.
T'POL:
HOW LONG WILL YOU BE GONE?
ARCHER: CLOSE TO THREE DAYS.
THE CIRCUMFERENCE
IS NEARLY A BILLION KILOMETERS.
WE'LL BE SCANNING
SURFACE FEATURES
THAT ARE UNDETECTABLE
FROM HIGHER ALTITUDES.
T'POL: THREE DAYS IS
A LONG TIME TO BE CONFINED
TO SUCH A SMALL CRAFT,
ESPECIALLY WITH A PERSON
YOU'VE JUST MET.
ARCHER: I THINK I'LL SURVIVE.
THESE PEOPLE ARE FASCINATING,
T'POL.
THEY HAVE A LOT TO OFFER US.
"THIS COULD BE THE BEGINNING
OF A BEAUTIFUL RELATIONSHIP."
WHICH REMINDS ME...
THEY'VE ASKED US
FOR A SAMPLING OF FILMS.
I PUT TOGETHER
A FEW SUGGESTIONS.
T'POL: I'LL SEE TO IT.
ARCHER: YOU'RE IN CHARGE.
T'POL:
OF THE SHIP OR THE MOVIES?
COMMANDER.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN LEFT YET?
T'POL:
HE'LL BE GONE FOR THREE DAYS.
HE ASKED
THAT YOU DOWNLOAD THESE FILMS
AND TRANSFER THEM
TO THE VISSIANS' DATABASE.
[TUCKER SIGHS]
TUCKER:
DID YOU MEET THEIR ENGINEER?
T'POL: BRIEFLY.
TUCKER: HE AND HIS WIFE
ARE TRYING TO HAVE A BABY.
T'POL: HOW INTERESTING.
TUCKER: THERE WAS
SOMEONE ELSE WITH THEM.
THEY CALLED HER A "COGENITOR."
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
T'POL: A THIRD GENDER.
WHY DO YOU CALL IT "HER"?
TUCKER: WELL, SHE LOOKS MORE
LIKE A HER THAN A HIM.
THEY TREAT HER LIKE A PET.
KEPT IN A ROOM, NOT TAUGHT
TO READ OR WRITE, NO NAME.
PORTHOS HAS A NAME.
T'POL: IT'S NOT OUR PLACE
TO JUDGE
THE CUSTOMS OF OTHER CULTURES.
TUCKER: WE'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT TAKING YOUR SHOES OFF
WHEN YOU WALK
INTO SOMEONE'S HOUSE.
THIS COGENITOR'S TREATED
LIKE ONE OF PHLOX'S LEECHES.
YOU PULL IT OUT OF ITS TANK
WHEN YOU NEED IT,
THEN YOU THROW IT BACK IN.
T'POL: TRI-GENDER REPRODUCTION
IS NOT UNCOMMON.
TUCKER: THAT'S NOT WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
THIS IS A QUESTION OF...
HUMAN RIGHTS.
T'POL: THEY'RE NOT HUMAN.
CAPTAIN ARCHER HOPES TO DEVELOP
A PRODUCTIVE RELATIONSHIP
WITH THIS SPECIES.
IT MIGHT BE BEST IF YOU KEPT
YOUR OPINIONS TO YOURSELF.
PHLOX: IT'S GOOD ADVICE.
MATING HABITS ARE OFTEN
QUITE, UH, PERSONAL, HMM?
SOME SPECIES AREN'T COMFORTABLE
DISCUSSING THEM.
TUCKER: I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN DISCUSSING THEIR HABITS.
I'M CONCERNED WITH THE WAY
THEY TREAT THIS COGENITOR.
PHLOX: THEY'RE MOST LIKELY
ONE AND THE SAME.
TUCKER: YEAH, WELL,
THAT DOESN'T MAKE IT RIGHT.
PHLOX: IT'S NOT A QUESTION
OF RIGHT OR WRONG.
TUCKER: YOU SCANNED THEM
WHEN THEY CAME ON BOARD.
DON'T YOU ALWAYS DO THAT?
PHLOX: YEAH. THEY WEREN'T
CARRYING ANY PATHOGENS
THAT WOULD BE DANGEROUS
TO OUR CREW.
TUCKER: IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU CAN TELL ME
ABOUT THE MENTAL CAPACITY
OF THIS COGENITOR?
IS IT ANY DIFFERENT
THAN THE MALES AND FEMALES?
[PHLOX CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
PHLOX: I'M AFRAID I DIDN'T
TAKE ANY, UH, NEURAL SCANS.
TUCKER:
IS THAT SOMETHING I COULD DO?
PHLOX: WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO?
TUCKER: JUST CURIOUS.
PHLOX: I SUPPOSE YOU COULD.
REED: FRUIT AND CHEESE
OFTEN COMPLEMENT EACH OTHER.
VEYLO: SO CHEESE
COMES IN EIGHT VARIETIES?
REED: ACTUALLY, THERE ARE
HUNDREDS, MAYBE THOUSANDS.
VEYLO:
WHAT MADE YOU CHOOSE THESE?
REED:
THEY HAVE THE STRONGEST SMELLS
OF ANYTHING WE HAVE ON BOARD.
YOU SAID OUR FOOD
WAS AROMATICALLY BLAND.
I THOUGHT THIS MIGHT
CHANGE YOUR MIND.
TRY SOME.
VEYLO: MILD BUT VERY NICE.
REED: HOW ABOUT...
THIS ONE?
VEYLO:
THE ODOR IS A LITTLE SPICIER.
WHAT'S IT CALLED?
REED: STILTON. CHEF SAYS
IT'S PRETTY PUNGENT.
VEYLO: HAVEN'T YOU
EVER TRIED IT?
REED: NOT FOR A LONG TIME.
VEYLO: HERE.
REED: WELL, I'D SAY THAT'S
MORE THAN A LITTLE SPICY.
MMM.
VEYLO: AND WHAT'S THIS CALLED?
REED: ALSATIAN MUENSTER.
VEYLO: INTERESTING.
DON'T YOU FIND IT SENSUAL?
REED: VERY.
VEYLO:
CAN WE VISIT THE ARMORY LATER?
I'M ANXIOUS TO SEE
YOUR TACTICAL ARRAY.
REED:
THERE'S AN OLD EARTH EXPRESSION.
"I'LL SHOW YOU MINE IF..."
[REED CHUCKLES]
YOU SHOW ME YOURS."
DRENNIK: YOUR FATHER!
THAT'S HARD TO IMAGINE.
THE MEN WHO DEVELOPED
WARP DRIVE ON MY WORLD
LIVED NEARLY
A THOUSAND YEARS AGO.
ARCHER: I'M SURPRISED
YOUR ANCESTORS
NEVER MADE IT TO EARTH.
DRENNIK: WE DON'T BELIEVE IN
TRAVELING GREAT DISTANCES.
THERE'S FAR TOO MUCH TO SEE
CLOSE TO HOME.
ARCHER: WELL, MAYBE NOW
YOU HAVE A REASON TO VISIT US.
IT'S NOT THAT FAR.
DRENNIK: I'M SURE WE CAN
MAKE AN EXCEPTION.
I'M GOING TO TAKE US DOWN TO
THE EDGE OF THE PHOTOSPHERE.
IT MIGHT GET A LITTLE TURBULENT.
ARCHER: FINE WITH ME.
ENGINEER: WHEN THE ENGINE
REACHES CRITICAL MASS,
A MIXTURE OF POSITRONS
AND NEUTRINOS
IS INJECTED INTO THE CHAMBER.
WATCH.
TUCKER: HMM.
THE EFFICIENCY IS UP OVER 30%.
PRETTY IMPRESSIVE.
ENGINEER:
IT'S POSSIBLE THIS TECHNOLOGY
COULD BE MODIFIED
FOR "ENTERPRISE."
TUCKER: WE'D BE VERY GRATEFUL.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY
MARRIED COUPLES ON "ENTERPRISE."
DO THEY GIVE YOU
SPECIAL QUARTERS?
ENGINEER:
THE CAPTAIN'S VERY GENEROUS.
TUCKER: OH, I WISH OURS WAS.
I'VE GOT A ROOM NOT HALF
THE SIZE OF THIS ONE.
I'D LOVE TO GET A LOOK
AT YOUR QUARTERS SOMETIME.
IF I COULD DESCRIBE IT
TO CAPTAIN ARCHER,
HE MIGHT CONSIDER EXPANDING
MY LIVING SPACE.
ENGINEER: OH, WHY DON'T YOU
JOIN US FOR DINNER TONIGHT?
YOU DID AGREE TO TRY OUR FOOD.
TUCKER: ARE YOU TELLING ME
YOU HAVE A DINING ROOM?
ENGINEER: WE'LL TRY NOT
TO PREPARE ANYTHING TOO PUNGENT.
TUCKER: MMM.
IT'S PRETTY MILD,
CONSIDERING THE, UM...SMELL.
CALLA: FOR US, THE AROMA IS
FAR MORE IMPORTANT
THAN THE TASTE.
TUCKER: THIS MUST
HAVE TAKEN YOU ALL DAY.
CALLA: IF I HAD ALL DAY,
I WOULD HAVE PREPARED
A FAR MORE SCENTED MEAL.
ENGINEER: CALLA'S IN CHARGE
OF THE MICROGRAVITY LAB.
WE USUALLY DON'T HAVE
MUCH TIME FOR COOKING.
TUCKER: WILL YOUR COGENITOR
BE JOINING US?
ENGINEER: IT RARELY EATS
MORE THAN ONE MEAL A DAY.
TUCKER: OH,
SO IN OUR MESS HALL...
CALLA: BRINGING THE COGENITOR
TO YOUR SHIP
WAS AN EXCEPTION.
TUCKER: TOO BAD.
I WAS HOPING TO SAY HELLO.
CALLA:
WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO DO THAT?
ENGINEER:
COMMANDER TUCKER IS VERY CURIOUS
ABOUT OUR REPRODUCTIVE PROCESS.
HUMANS ARE BI-GENDERED.
CALLA: I'LL SEE IF IT'S AWAKE.
TUCKER:
WHICH ONE'S THE COGENITOR?
PHLOX: RIGHT HERE.
HER SYNAPTIC DENSITY
AND NEURAL MASS
ARE ALMOST IDENTICAL
TO THE OTHER TWO.
YOUR COGENITOR APPEARS TO BE
NO MORE OR LESS INTELLIGENT
THAN THE MALE AND FEMALE.
ARCHER: I WOULDN'T MIND
TAKING A TURN AT THE HELM.
DRENNIK: OUR NAVIGATION
CONTROLS ARE NOT LIKE YOURS.
THEY'RE BASED ON
FIVE SPATIAL AXES.
ARCHER: I'VE BEEN WATCHING YOU.
I THINK I CAN HANDLE IT.
[DRENNIK SIGHS]
DRENNIK: YOU OBVIOUSLY
HAVE SOME EXPERIENCE.
ARCHER: A LITTLE.
THERE'S A PRETTY
BIG FLARE FORMING BELOW US.
I THINK I CAN LOOP AROUND IT,
LET YOU GET A BETTER SCAN.
DRENNIK: IT'S GIVING OFF
A LOT OF MAGNETIC FLUX.
IT MAY CAUSE FALSE READINGS
IN THE NAVIGATION SENSORS.
ARCHER:
I'LL KEEP AN EYE ON IT.
TUCKER: SO BY ROTATING
THE QUANTUM INVERTERS,
YOU'VE TRIPLED
THE ANTIMATTER FLUX?
ENGINEER: EXACTLY.
THREE MORE AND I'LL BE FINISHED.
TUCKER: I HAVEN'T EATEN
ANYTHING SINCE THIS MORNING.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'LL GO TO YOUR MESS HALL,
SEE WHAT THEY'RE SERVING.
ENGINEER:
IF YOU CAN WAIT UNTIL I'M DONE,
I'LL SHOW YOU HOW TO GET THERE.
TUCKER: I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M SURE I CAN FIND THE WAY.
SEE YOU IN A LITTLE WHILE.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COGENITOR: THEY'RE NOT HERE.
TUCKER: I CAME TO SEE YOU.
COGENITOR: WHY?
TUCKER: I BROUGHT YOU THIS.
IT'LL TEACH YOU HOW TO READ.
TUCKER: NOW YOU TRY IT.
COGENITOR: I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
TUCKER: YOU JUST TOUCH THE WORD,
THEN YOU'LL HEAR IT PRONOUNCED.
GO AHEAD. TRY IT.
DEVICE: TODAY.
TUCKER: THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW GO TO THE NEXT ONE.
DEVICE: TODAY WE'RE...
TUCKER: GOOD. AGAIN.
COGENITOR:
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
IT'S NOT RIGHT FOR ME TO READ.
TUCKER: WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
COGENITOR:
YOU SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
[TUCKER SIGHS]
TUCKER:
YOU'RE AS CAPABLE AS THEY ARE,
AS SMART AS THEY ARE.
COGENITOR: THAT'S NOT TRUE.
THEY NEED ME TO HAVE CHILDREN.
TUCKER: IT'S NOT A QUESTION
OF WHAT THEY NEED.
YOU HAVE THE SAME RIGHTS--
TO LEARN, TO CHOOSE
HOW YOU'RE GOING TO LIVE,
TO HAVE A NAME.
COGENITOR: THAT MAY BE
TRUE ON YOUR WORLD,
BUT NOT ON MINE.
TUCKER: WHEN CALLA GIVES BIRTH,
WHO'S GONNA RAISE THE BABY?
WHO'S GONNA TAKE CARE OF IT?
COGENITOR: THEY WILL.
TUCKER: WHY?
YOU'RE JUST AS CRUCIAL IN
CREATING THE CHILD AS THEY ARE.
COGENITOR:
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
TUCKER: OK, MAYBE.
BUT WE TOOK SCANS.
MY DOCTOR SAYS YOU HAVE
THE SAME POTENTIAL AS THEY DO.
THE ONLY THING THAT SETS YOU
APART IS YOUR GENDER.
YOU'RE NO MORE DIFFERENT
THAN THEY ARE FROM EACH OTHER.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER WISHED
YOU COULD READ?
IT WON'T HURT YOU, YOU KNOW.
THERE'S NOTHING TO BE AFRAID OF.
DEVICE: TODAY WE'RE GOING...
TODAY WE'RE GOING TO...
TODAY WE'RE GOING TO READ.
ARCHER: I'M STARTING
TO GET THE HANG OF THIS.
I COULD TAKE US DOWN
A LITTLE CLOSER IF YOU'D LIKE.
DRENNIK: ANOTHER 10,000 METERS,
AND I'LL BE ABLE TO GET
A PARTICLE COUNT
OF THE PHOTOSPHERE.
ARCHER: AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
10,000 METERS IT IS.
DRENNIK: ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
ARCHER: ABSOLUTELY.
DRENNIK: IF YOU CAN
KEEP US AT THIS ALTITUDE
A LITTLE WHILE LONGER...
ARCHER: NO PROBLEM.
VEYLO: ARE THESE ARMED
WITH PHOTONIC WARHEADS?
REED: PHOTONIC?
I'M NOT FAMILIAR WITH THAT.
VEYLO: I'M AFRAID OUR WEAPONS
ARE SOMEWHAT MORE SOPHISTICATED
THAN YOURS.
REED: THIS TECHNOLOGY MUST SEEM
PRETTY ANTIQUATED TO YOU.
VEYLO: WHERE I COME FROM,
ANTIQUATED CAN BE VERY QUAINT.
REED: IS THAT HOW YOU SEE US?
QUAINT?
VEYLO: AND CHARMING.
WHAT SORT OF POWER SOURCE
DO THESE USE?
REED: SARIUM MICROCELLS.
I SUPPOSE THAT'S
VERY QUAINT, TOO.
VEYLO: NOT AT ALL.
WE CHARGE OUR WEAPONS
THE SAME WAY.
REED: MAYBE YOU'D LIKE TO SEE
THE PHASE CANNON ASSEMBLY.
VEYLO: PLEASE.
REED: AFTER YOU.
IT HAS
MULTIPHASIC EMITTERS...
AND A MAXIMUM YIELD
OF 80 GIGAJOULES.
VEYLO: IMPRESSIVE.
REED: I'M SORRY
IT'S SO CRAMPED IN HERE.
VEYLO: DON'T BE.
I WANTED TO GET A LITTLE
CLOSER TO YOU ALL DAY.
REED: REALLY?
VEYLO: I WAS HOPING TO SPEND
SOME INTIMATE TIME WITH YOU.
MAYBE WE COULD
SLEEP TOGETHER TONIGHT.
REED: OH!
ON EARTH...
IT'S CUSTOMARY TO ASK
A WOMAN TO DINNER FIRST
BEFORE SPENDING
THE NIGHT WITH HER.
VEYLO:
IT'S VERY DIFFERENT ON VISSIA.
IT'S ONLY WHEN A WOMAN ENJOYS
HER INTIMATE TIME WITH A MAN
THAT SHE'LL JOIN HIM FOR DINNER.
COGENITOR: "THE DIDIRON MOUNTAIN
RANGE RUNS THROUGH
THE UPPER PLAINS
OF THE GREAT CONTINENT."
TUCKER: AMAZING.
COGENITOR: THE TEXT DESCRIBES
FAR MORE IMPRESSIVE PEAKS.
TUCKER: I DON'T MEAN
THE MOUNTAINS.
I MEAN YOUR READING.
COGENITOR: "THE FAUNA AND FLORA
VARY GREATLY
ON EITHER SIDE
OF THE CENTRAL PLATEAU."
TUCKER: LOOK HOW
MUCH YOU'VE ACCOMPLISHED
IN A SINGLE DAY.
AND READING'S JUST
THE TIP OF THE ICEBERG.
YOU COULD STUDY
ALL SORTS OF THINGS.
HISTORY, SCIENCE.
ENGINEERING'S NOT BAD.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SIT
IN THIS ROOM ALL DAY.
COGENITOR: THEY WOULD NEVER
LET ME LEARN THOSE THINGS.
TUCKER: THEN YOU'VE GOT
TO CONVINCE THEM.
IT'S NOT JUST LEARNING.
IT'S--IT'S EXPERIENCING THINGS.
MUSIC, SWIMMING IN THE OCEAN.
YOU DO HAVE OCEANS
ON YOUR PLANET?
COGENITOR: YES.
TUCKER: AND HOW ABOUT
THOSE DIDIRON MOUNTAINS?
READING ABOUT THEM IS ONE THING.
CLIMBING THEM IS ANOTHER.
COGENITOR:
I'D LIKE TO CLIMB A MOUNTAIN.
TUCKER: THERE YOU GO. THAT--
THAT'S THE RIGHT ATTITUDE.
YOU KEEP AT IT.
I'VE GOT TO GET BACK.
THEY THINK I'M AT
THE ASTROMETRICS LAB.
BUT I'LL SEE YOU
AS SOON AS I CAN.
COGENITOR: TRIP?
TUCKER: YEAH?
COGENITOR: I'D LIKE MY NAME
TO BE TRIP, JUST LIKE YOURS.
TUCKER:
ACTUALLY, MY NAME IS CHARLES.
COGENITOR: THEN I WOULD LIKE
MY NAME TO BE CHARLES.
TUCKER: I'M FLATTERED.
DRENNIK:
THERE'S A FLARE FORMING AHEAD.
ARCHER: I DON'T SEE IT.
DRENNIK: YOU WILL.
TURN THE AXIS
40 DEGREES TO PORT.
I THINK WE CAN BANK AROUND IT.
ARCHER: IT'S TOO BIG.
DRENNIK: TAKE US UP.
TRY TO GET OVER IT.
ARCHER:
WE'RE NOT GONNA MAKE IT.
DRENNIK: INCREASE SPEED.
ARCHER: IT WON'T BE ENOUGH.
DRENNIK: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
ARCHER:
IF YOU CAN'T GET OVER A WAVE,
YOU GOT TO DIVE THROUGH IT.
DRENNIK:
WHERE DID YOU LEARN TO DO THAT?
ARCHER: NORTH SHORE OF OAHU.
BODY SURFING.
DRENNIK: I THINK IT'S TIME
YOU TOOK THE HELM BACK.
CHARLES: WOULD YOU BE PUNISHED
IF THEY FIND OUT
YOU'VE BROUGHT ME HERE?
TUCKER: PUNISHED? NO.
BUT THEY MIGHT GET
A LITTLE ANGRY.
CHARLES: I WOULD BE PUNISHED.
TUCKER:
MAYBE I SHOULD TAKE YOU BACK.
CHARLES:
NO, NO, I WANT TO SEE MORE.
TUCKER: OK. WE'LL JUST HAVE
TO BE SURE NO ONE SPOTS US.
THIS IS OUR TRANSPORTER.
IT TURNS THINGS
INTO A MATTER STREAM
THAT CAN BE SENT
JUST ABOUT ANYWHERE,
WITHIN 2,000 KILOMETERS OR SO.
THEN IT GETS REASSEMBLED.
CHARLES:
COULD IT SEND A VISSIAN?
TUCKER: I DON'T SEE WHY NOT.
CHARLES: I'D LIKE TO TRY.
TUCKER: I DON'T THINK THAT
WOULD BE A GOOD IDEA.
CHARLES:
COULD I SEE WHERE YOU WORK?
TUCKER: SURE. FOLLOW ME.
COAST IS CLEAR.
THAT'S OUR MAIN ENGINE--
FASTEST ONE IN STARFLEET.
I'VE HAD IT UP TO WARP 5.1.
CHARLES: I THINK MY SHIP
HAS SOMETHING LIKE THIS,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN IT.
TUCKER: HA HA!
YOUR SHIP HAS AN ENGINE
THAT'S A LOT MORE SOPHISTICATED
THAN THIS ONE.
CHARLES: DO YOU LIVE HERE?
TUCKER: UH, NO.
MY QUARTERS ARE ON "B" DECK.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN A MOVIE?
IT'S NOT EASY PICKING A MOVIE
FOR SOMEBODY WHO'S
NEVER SEEN ONE BEFORE.
WHAT WOULD YOU THINK
ABOUT A WESTERN?
NO, NOT A WESTERN.
I DON'T THINK A MUSICAL
WOULD BE RIGHT, EITHER.
GOT IT.
"THE DAY THE EARTH STOOD STILL."
NOTHING LIKE A LITTLE
SCIENCE FICTION TO BREAK YOU IN.
CHARLES:
IT'S A STORY ABOUT YOUR PLANET?
TUCKER: YEAH, BUT IT'S FICTION.
THE EARTH NEVER
REALLY STOOD STILL.
SIT DOWN.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
CHARLES:
WHY WERE THE HUMANS SO AFRAID
OF KLAATU AND HIS ANDROID?
TUCKER: WELL,
BEFORE WE MADE FIRST CONTACT
WITH THE VULCANS,
THE PEOPLE OF EARTH
WERE PRETTY VIOLENT.
THEY HAD A HARD TIME
TRUSTING THINGS
THEY DIDN'T UNDERSTAND.
THE CHARACTERS IN THE FILM
KNEW NOTHING ABOUT KLAATU--
WHO HE WAS,
WHERE HE CAME FROM--
SO THEY TRIED TO KILL HIM.
CHARLES: I UNDERSTAND.
DOES THIS MEAN I'VE WON?
TUCKER: NO ONE'S BEATEN ME
AT THIS IN THE LAST 2 YEARS.
CHARLES:
TELL ME ABOUT WESTERNS.
MAYBE I COULD
WATCH A WESTERN NEXT.
TUCKER: IT'S GETTING LATE.
WE BETTER GET YOU BACK
BEFORE THEY REALIZE YOU'RE GONE.
T'POL: I HAVE BEEN TOLD
YOU'RE NO LONGER WELCOME
ABOARD THE VISSIAN SHIP.
WHY?
TUCKER: I WASN'T EXACTLY
WHERE I WAS SUPPOSED TO BE.
T'POL: NO, YOU WEREN'T.
YOU TOLD THEM YOU WERE GOING
TO THE ASTROMETRICS LAB.
THEY TRIED TO CONTACT YOU,
BUT YOU WEREN'T THERE.
THEN THEY TRIED THEIR MESS HALL.
YOU WEREN'T THERE EITHER.
TUCKER:
I WAS WITH THE COGENITOR.
T'POL: WHERE?
TUCKER:
AT FIRST IN HER QUARTERS.
ACTUALLY, THEY'RE
NOT HER QUARTERS.
THEY BELONG TO
THE CHIEF ENGINEER AND HIS WIFE.
SHE GETS A ROOM TO SLEEP IN,
AND IF SHE'S REAL GOOD,
SHE CAN USE THEIR LIVING SPACE.
T'POL: WHY WERE YOU THERE?
TUCKER:
I'M TEACHING HER HOW TO READ.
T'POL: HER EDUCATION
IS NOT YOUR CONCERN.
TUCKER: WHAT EDUCATION?
T'POL: WHERE ELSE DID YOU GO?
TUCKER: I BROUGHT HER HERE,
GAVE HER A LITTLE TOUR,
SHOWED HER A MOVIE.
T'POL: IT APPEARS YOU'RE
DOING EVERYTHING YOU CAN
TO UNDERMINE
THE CAPTAIN'S WISHES.
TUCKER: ONE DAY.
THAT'S ALL IT TOOK HER.
IN ONE DAY, SHE WAS READING
A GEOGRAPHY TEXT.
T'POL: FIRST CONTACTS
ARE IMPORTANT TO THE CAPTAIN.
YOU MAY VERY WELL HAVE
DAMAGED THIS ONE IRREPARABLY.
TUCKER: YOU'RE NOT LISTENING
TO A WORD I'M SAYING.
[CHARLES CLEARS THROAT]
TUCKER: OH, I DIDN'T SEE YOU.
HOW YOU DOING?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
CHARLES:
THEY DON'T WANT TO HELP ME.
THEY DON'T WANT ME
TO CLIMB MOUNTAINS.
TUCKER:
DON'T WORRY. THEY WILL.
GIVE IT TIME.
CHARLES: THEY'RE ANGRY WITH YOU.
THEY'LL LEAVE AS SOON
AS OUR CAPTAIN RETURNS.
THEY WON'T HELP ME.
BUT YOU CAN.
I WANT TO STAY HERE, PLEASE.
ARCHER: ARCHER TO "ENTERPRISE."
T'POL: Go ahead.
ARCHER:
THAT WAS ONE HELL OF A RIDE.
HA HA! I'LL TELL YOU ABOUT IT
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF DATA
TO DOWNLOAD
INTO THEIR COMPUTERS.
T'POL: I think it would be best
if you come back
immediately, sir.
There's been an incident.
ARCHER: WHERE IS SHE?
TUCKER:
IT'S NOT EXACTLY A SHE, SIR.
ARCHER: WHERE?
TUCKER: IN MY QUARTERS.
ARCHER:
HOW LONG AGO DID THIS HAPPEN?
TUCKER:
LAST NIGHT AFTER SUPPER.
T'POL: THEY DEMANDED THAT
SHE BE RETURNED IMMEDIATELY.
TUCKER: I DID EXACTLY
WHAT YOU'D DO, CAPTAIN.
IT'S NOT LIKE I HAD MUCH CHOICE.
I WASN'T GONNA JUST--
ARCHER: WILL YOU EXCUSE US,
SUB-COMMANDER?
I MIGHT HAVE EXPECTED
SOMETHING LIKE THIS
FROM A FIRST-YEAR RECRUIT
BUT NOT YOU.
YOU DID EXACTLY WHAT I'D DO?
IF THAT'S TRUE, THEN I'VE DONE
A PRETTY LOUSY JOB
SETTING AN EXAMPLE AROUND HERE.
YOU'RE A SENIOR OFFICER
ON THIS SHIP.
YOU'RE PRIVY TO THE MORAL
CHALLENGES I'VE HAD TO FACE.
YOU KNOW I'VE WRESTLED
WITH THE FINE LINE
BETWEEN DOING
WHAT I THINK IS RIGHT
AND INTERFERING
WITH OTHER SPECIES.
SO DON'T TELL ME YOU KNOW
WHAT I WOULD HAVE DONE
WHEN I DON'T EVEN
KNOW WHAT I WOULD HAVE DONE.
TUCKER: I DIDN'T
THINK IT WOULD HURT
TO TEACH HER HOW TO READ.
ARCHER: THEN YOU DIDN'T
THINK HARD ENOUGH.
WE'RE OUT HERE
TO MEET NEW SPECIES,
NOT TELL THEM WHAT TO DO.
TUCKER: TEACHING HER TO READ
IS NO DIFFERENT
THAN YOU GIVING THEM
BOOKS OR MOVIES.
ARCHER: GIVING THEM BOOKS
IS A LOT DIFFERENT
THAN SUGGESTING
THEY DEFY THEIR CULTURE.
AND THEY ASKED ME FOR THE BOOKS.
DID SHE ASK YOU
TO TEACH HER HOW TO READ?
TUCKER: NO, SIR.
ARCHER:
AND SNEAKING INTO HER QUARTERS,
BRINGING HER ON "ENTERPRISE,"
LYING ABOUT
WHERE YOU WERE GOING, WHY?
COME WITH ME.
CHARLES: YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I CAN'T GO BACK.
ARCHER:
JUST UNTIL WE RESOLVE THIS.
CHARLES: TRIP SAID I HAVE
THE SAME RIGHTS AS THEY DO.
ARCHER: IT'S NOT
OUR PLACE TO TELL YOU
WHAT RIGHTS YOU HAVE.
I'M SORRY.
CHARLES: ARE YOU
GOING TO FORCE ME TO LEAVE?
DRENNIK: SOME MEN CAN WORK
TOGETHER FOR YEARS
WITHOUT CREATING THE FRIENDSHIP
AND BOND
THAT WE DID IN ONLY TWO DAYS.
I'M CERTAIN WE CAN RESOLVE THIS.
ARCHER: I'M AFRAID IT MAY NOT
BE THAT SIMPLE.
ON MY WORLD
WHEN SOMEONE ASKS FOR ASYLUM,
IT HAS TO BE GIVEN
SERIOUS CONSIDERATION.
DRENNIK:
WE'RE NOT ON YOUR WORLD.
AND I DOUBT WHETHER THIS PERSON
TRULY UNDERSTOOD
WHAT YOUR ENGINEER
WAS SUGGESTING.
ARCHER:
I'VE BEEN TOLD THIS PERSON IS
JUST AS CAPABLE OF UNDERSTANDING
AS ANY OF YOU ARE.
ENGINEER:
WHY ARE WE DEBATING THIS?
THE COGENITOR BELONGS
ON OUR SHIP.
OR ARE YOU SUGGESTING
MY WIFE AND I
ABANDON OUR PLANS
TO HAVE A CHILD?
ARCHER: I'VE BEEN ASKED
TO GIVE SANCTUARY
TO SOMEONE WHO BELIEVES
SHE'S BEEN TREATED UNFAIRLY.
I CAN'T IGNORE THAT.
CALLA: WE'RE THE ONES
BEING TREATED UNFAIRLY.
DO YOU KNOW HOW LONG
WE'VE WAITED
TO BE GIVEN A COGENITOR?
ARCHER: GIVEN?
YOU SOUND LIKE YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT
SOME INANIMATE OBJECT.
ENGINEER:
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT TO JUDGE US.
YOU KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT OUR CULTURE.
WHAT IF ONE OF YOUR STEWARDS,
THE MEN WHO ARE
FORCED TO SERVE YOU FOOD--
WHAT IF THEY SHOULD ASK US
FOR ASYLUM?
ARCHER: THEY'RE NOT
FORCED TO DO ANYTHING.
ENGINEER: I APOLOGIZE.
BUT IT'S EASY
TO MISUNDERSTAND SOMEONE
WHEN YOU KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT THEIR CULTURE.
ARCHER: YOU CAN'T EXPECT
ME TO IGNORE SOMEONE
WHEN THEY ASK FOR MY PROTECTION.
DRENNIK:
WE'RE IN NO RUSH TO LEAVE.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
CONSIDER WHAT WE'VE SAID.
T'POL:
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE MISGIVINGS.
YOU'VE MADE THE RIGHT CHOICE.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR CHIMES]
[MUSIC SHUTS OFF]
TUCKER: COME IN.
DRENNIK: CAPTAIN ARCHER.
ARCHER: I'M AFRAID SHAKESPEARE
ONLY WROTE 36 PLAYS.
SO IT MIGHT BE BEST IF YOU
TAKE YOUR TIME MEMORIZING THEM.
DRENNIK: BY ALL MEANS.
I HOPE YESTERDAY'S
UNFORTUNATE INCIDENT
WON'T INTERFERE
WITH FUTURE RELATIONS
BETWEEN OUR PEOPLE.
ARCHER:
YOU SURE YOU DON'T HAVE
AN EXTRA STRATOPOD
YOU COULD SPARE?
DRENNIK:
I'M SURE YOUR STARFLEET
WILL DEVELOP ONE SOON ENOUGH.
GOOD-BYE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: SAFE JOURNEY.
TIME TO SAY GOOD-BYE
TO THE HYPERGIANT.
PREPARE TO GET UNDER WAY,
TRAVIS.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
GO AHEAD.
HOSHI: There's a call coming in
from the Vissian captain, sir.
He sounds upset.
ARCHER: PUT HIM THROUGH.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
TUCKER:
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: I WAS JUST TOLD THAT
THE VISSIAN COGENITOR DIED.
TUCKER: WHAT?
HOW?
ARCHER: SUICIDE, TRIP.
SHE KILLED HERSELF.
TUCKER: THAT CAN'T BE. WHY--
IT'S MY FAULT.
I'M RESPONSIBLE.
ARCHER: YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT
YOU ARE.
AND IT'S NOT JUST HER.
THERE'S A CHILD
WHO WON'T BE CONCEIVED
BECAUSE OF THIS...
AT LEAST NOT FOR A LONG WHILE.
IT'S TIME YOU LEARNED TO WEIGH
THE POSSIBLE REPERCUSSIONS
OF YOUR ACTIONS.
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN IMPULSIVE.
MAYBE THIS WILL
TEACH YOU A LESSON.
TUCKER: I UNDERSTAND.
ARCHER: DO YOU?
I'M NOT SO SURE YOU DO.
YOU KNEW YOU HAD NO BUSINESS
INTERFERING WITH THOSE PEOPLE.
BUT YOU JUST COULDN'T
LET IT ALONE.
YOU THOUGHT YOU WERE
DOING THE RIGHT THING.
I MIGHT AGREE IF THIS WAS
FLORIDA OR SINGAPORE.
BUT IT'S NOT, IS IT?
WE'RE IN DEEP SPACE,
AND A PERSON IS DEAD.
A PERSON WHO'D STILL BE ALIVE
IF WE HADN'T MADE FIRST CONTACT.
I GUESS I HAVEN'T BEEN
VERY SUCCESSFUL
AT GETTING THROUGH TO YOU.
IF I HAD, YOU WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
A LOT HARDER
BEFORE DOING WHAT YOU DID.
TUCKER: YOU'RE NOT RESPONSIBLE.
ARCHER: DISMISSED.
TUCKER: CAPTAIN?