DRAKE:
I THINK THIS IS THE PLACE.
MONINGER: TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
ROONEY: OVER HERE!
SINGER:
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
MONINGER: DEFINITELY HUMANOID,
BUT I DON'T RECOGNIZE
THE SPECIES.
DRAKE: SEEMS VERY
WELL-PRESERVED.
MONINGER: GETTING HIM
OUT OF HERE'S
GOING TO BE
A DELICATE OPERATION.
DRAKE: DRAKE TO ARCTIC ONE.
MAN ON ARCTIC ONE: Go ahead.
DRAKE: SET UP A BASE CAMP.
GET ALPHA TEAM STARTED.
MAN ON ARCTIC ONE: Acknowledged.
DRAKE: CONTACT STARFLEET.
TELL COMMANDER WILLIAMS
HE OWES ME A BOTTLE OF SCOTCH.
MAN ON ARCTIC ONE: Sir?
DRAKE: HE'LL KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS. DRAKE OUT.
ROONEY:
I'M PICKING UP E.M. TRACES
A FEW DOZEN METERS
UNDER THE GLACIER.
THERE'S A LOT MORE HERE
THAN WE'RE SEEING.
WE'VE GOT ANOTHER ONE!
DRAKE: I GIVE UP. WHAT IS IT?
MONINGER: AN ARM. IT'S HIS.
DRAKE: YOU'RE JOKING.
MONINGER: FROM WHAT
I CAN TELL, IT WAS INTEGRATED
INTO HIS CIRCULATORY
AND NERVOUS SYSTEMS.
HE COULD PROBABLY
OPERATE IT
LIKE IT WAS HIS
OWN FLESH AND BLOOD.
DRAKE: I MET A VULCAN SCIENTIST
WHO WORE A PROSTHESIS.
HE LOST HIS FOREARM.
IT'S PRETTY SOPHISTICATED,
BUT IT DOESN'T COMPARE TO THIS.
MONINGER:
TAKE A LOOK AT THE EYEPIECE.
JUDGING BY THE OPTICS,
I'D SAY HE COULD
SEE MOST OF THE E.M. SPECTRUM.
DRAKE:
DID YOU RUN A GENETIC ANALYSIS?
MONINGER:
THAT'S EVEN MORE INTERESTING.
THEY DON'T HAVE MUCH
IN COMMON.
THEY BELONG
TO TWO DIFFERENT SPECIES.
DRAKE: TRANSMIT YOUR FINDINGS
TO STARFLEET.
MAYBE THEY'LL FIND A MATCH
IN THEIR DATABASE.
MONINGER: RIGHT AWAY.
ROONEY: SIR, I'VE RUN EVERY TEST
IN THE BOOK.
I STILL CAN'T IDENTIFY
THIS ALLOY.
DRAKE: WHAT ABOUT THIS?
ROONEY: WELL, I THOUGHT IT
WAS SIMPLE THERMAL DAMAGE
UNTIL I FOUND SIGNS
OF ANTIMATTER RESIDUE.
DRAKE: MAYBE THEIR WARP DRIVE
OVERLOADED.
ROONEY: THAT COULD EXPLAIN
WHY THERE'S NOT MUCH DEBRIS.
I DID FIND SOME CARBON TRACES.
DRAKE: COULD YOU DATE THEM?
ROONEY: THIS DEBRIS'S BEEN HERE
FOR ABOUT A HUNDRED YEARS.
[CLANKING]
MONINGER: TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
DO YOU SEE THOSE DEVICES?
THEY'RE
REPAIRING THE CELL MEMBRANES.
DRAKE: WHAT ARE THEY?
MONINGER:
I BELIEVE YOU'RE LOOKING AT
A FORM OF NANOTECHNOLOGY.
I FOUND THOUSANDS OF THESE
IN BOTH ALIENS.
THEY'RE NOT JUST REGENERATING
THE DAMAGED TISSUE.
THEY'RE REPAIRING THE MECHANICAL
COMPONENTS AS WELL.
AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
THIS ARM'S AS GOOD AS NEW.
DRAKE:
THE DENOBULANS HAVE EXPERIMENTED
WITH NANOTECHNOLOGY,
BUT THEY HAVE NOTHING
LIKE THIS.
MONINGER: MAYBE WE SHOULD
MOVE THE BODIES TO MODULE THREE,
PUT THEM BACK IN COLD STORAGE
WITH THE OTHER SAMPLES.
THAT WAY WE CAN EXAMINE
THEM LATER
UNDER CONTROLLED CONDITIONS.
DRAKE:
COULDN'T THE BODIES BE DAMAGED
IF WE FREEZE THEM AGAIN?
MONINGER: I GUESS IT'S POSSIBLE.
DRAKE:
THEN WE SHOULD LEAVE THEM HERE.
LET THE REGENERATION PROCESS
CONTINUE.
MONINGER: WHAT IF IT REVIVES
MORE OF THEIR SYSTEMS?
WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THIS SPECIES
OR WHAT THEY WERE DOING HERE
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO.
DRAKE: THERE'S NO REASON
TO ASSUME THEY'RE HOSTILE.
[MONINGER CHUCKLES]
MONINGER: THEY DON'T EXACTLY
LOOK FRIENDLY.
DRAKE: STARFLEET
HAS ASKED US TO FIND OUT
EVERYTHING WE CAN.
KEEP THEM HERE FOR NOW.
WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
DRAKE: ANYTHING?
ROONEY: OH!
PLENTY.
DRAKE: YOU SEEM A LITTLE JUMPY.
ROONEY: CYBERNETIC CORPSES,
DIGGING THROUGH FROZEN REMAINS
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT--
WHY WOULD I BE JUMPY?
DRAKE: I'D BE MORE WORRIED
ABOUT THE POLAR BEARS.
ROONEY: I'VE IDENTIFIED
22 FRAGMENTS OF THE OUTER HULL.
EACH ONE
HAS THE SAME CURVATURE.
I THINK THIS SHIP
WAS A PERFECT SPHERE.
DRAKE: HOW BIG?
ROONEY:
ABOUT 600 METERS IN DIAMETER.
DRAKE:
THE DEBRIS FIELD COULD BE
A LOT MORE EXTENSIVE
THAN WE THOUGHT.
WE MIGHT WANT TO GET ANOTHER
EXCAVATION TEAM OUT HERE.
[BEEPING]
WHAT IS IT?
ROONEY: A WARP SIGNATURE.
HELP ME WITH THIS.
MONINGER:
JUST WHAT THE DOCTOR ORDERED.
THANKS.
MAN: HOW ARE YOUR FRIENDS?
MONINGER:
A LITTLE ON THE QUIET SIDE.
MAN: THERE'S A BROKEN
HEATING UNIT IN MODULE THREE.
THEY'VE ASKED ME TO TAKE A LOOK.
WILL YOU BE ALL RIGHT HERE?
MONINGER: GO AHEAD.
I'LL BE FINE.
MAN: OK.
[WHIRRING]
MONINGER: FEELING BETTER?
ROONEY: DEUTERIUM RESIDUE.
MIGHT BE SOME KIND
OF WARP COIL.
DRAKE: SEEMS TOO SMALL
FOR A SHIP THIS SIZE.
ROONEY: I'D LIKE TO BRING
IT BACK TO THE LAB,
TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[ALIEN GASPS]
[MONINGER SCREAMING]
DRAKE: HERE, HERE.
ROONEY: OH.
[MONINGER GASPING]
DRAKE: GET ME A MEDICAL KIT.
[ROONEY GASPS]
WILLIAMS: ADMIRAL,
THERE'S A PROBLEM
WITH THE A-6 EXCAVATION TEAM.
THE SCIENCE COUNCIL
HASN'T HEARD FROM THEM
IN THREE DAYS.
FORREST: GET A SHUTTLE READY.
ARCHER: THE ADMIRAL THINKS
THAT THEY'RE HUMANOIDS,
ENHANCED WITH TECHNOLOGY.
HE BELIEVES THEY ABDUCTED
THE RESEARCH TEAM.
REED: WE'RE A LONG WAY
FROM THE ARCTIC.
WHAT CAN WE DO?
ARCHER: EARTH TRACKING STATIONS
SPOTTED THE TRANSPORT
LEAVING ORBIT AT WARP 3.9.
TUCKER: THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THOSE TRANSPORTS
CAN'T EXCEED 1.4.
ARCHER: I THINK IT'S SAFE
TO ASSUME THESE ALIENS
RECONFIGURED THE ENGINES
USING TECHNOLOGY
FROM THEIR OWN SHIP.
HOSHI: DOES STARFLEET KNOW
WHERE THE VESSEL IS NOW?
ARCHER: NOT EXACTLY,
BUT THEIR HEADING PUTS THEM
WITHIN A HALF-DOZEN LIGHT-YEARS
OF OUR CURRENT POSITION.
WE'VE BEEN ORDERED
TO FIND THE SHIP.
T'POL: IT SHOULDN'T BE DIFFICULT
TO ISOLATE THEIR WARP SIGNATURE.
ARCHER: WE'LL START
SEARCHING AT THESE COORDINATES.
GO TO TACTICAL ALERT.
LAY IN A COURSE.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
TUCKER: BURIED IN THE ICE
FOR A CENTURY.
ARCHER: HARD TO BELIEVE
ANYTHING COULD SURVIVE.
TUCKER: HANDSOME DEVIL.
PHLOX: YOU WANTED TO SEE ME,
LIEUTENANT?
REED: YES.
THE RESEARCHERS GATHERED
A GREAT DEAL OF BIOMETRIC DATA
ON THESE ALIENS,
BUT I'M HAVING TROUBLE MAKING
HEADS OR TAILS OF IT.
PHLOX: HOW CAN I HELP?
REED: WELL, THIS ARM MIGHT
CONTAIN SOME SORT OF WEAPON.
IF I CAN DETERMINE ITS YIELD,
WE'LL HAVE A BETTER IDEA
OF WHAT WE'RE FACING.
WHAT SORT OF PEOPLE
WOULD REPLACE
PERFECTLY GOOD BODY PARTS
WITH CYBERNETIC IMPLANTS?
PHLOX: YOU, OF ALL PEOPLE,
SHOULD BE OPEN-MINDED
ABOUT TECHNOLOGY.
REED: WELL,
I DON'T HAVE A PROBLEM WITH IT,
SO LONG AS IT STAYS
OUTSIDE OF MY SKIN.
PHLOX: IF YOUR HEART
WAS DAMAGED,
WOULD YOU WANT ME TO REPLACE IT
WITH A SYNTHETIC ORGAN
OR WOULD YOU RATHER DIE?
REED: THAT'S DIFFERENT.
PHLOX: HMM.
THERE'S A SPECIES
I ONCE ENCOUNTERED
IN THE BETA MAGELLAN SYSTEM--
THE BYNARS.
WHEN THEY'RE BORN,
A SURGEON REMOVES
THE CHILD'S PARIETAL LOBE
AND REPLACES IT
WITH A SYNAPTIC PROCESSOR.
I SAW THE PROCEDURE
PERFORMED ONCE.
IT WAS VERY IMPRESSIVE.
REED: YEAH, I'M SURE IT WAS.
ANYTHING?
PHLOX: I DON'T SEE
ANY EVIDENCE OF A WEAPON.
REED: THE RESEARCH TEAM
WAS HEAVILY ARMED.
HOW DID THESE ALIENS MANAGE
TO OVERPOWER THEM?
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI: Bridge to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
HOSHI: We're receiving
an automated distress call.
It's from a Tarkalean freighter.
HOSHI:
THERE'S A LOT OF INTERFERENCE.
"TO ANY SHIP WITHIN RANGE,
"WE'RE UNDER ATTACK
BY AN UNKNOWN SPECIES.
REQUEST IMMEDIATE ASSISTANCE."
THAT'S IT, SIR.
ARCHER: HOW LONG TO REACH THEM?
TRAVIS: ABOUT AN HOUR.
ARCHER: SET A COURSE.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER
OF THE STARFLEET VESSEL
"ENTERPRISE."
STAND DOWN YOUR ATTACK
OR WE'LL OPEN FIRE.
REED: THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
REED: SOME KIND OF PROTON BURST.
THOSE TRANSPORTS
AREN'T NORMALLY ARMED.
T'POL: OBVIOUSLY, THE ENGINES
AREN'T THE ONLY SYSTEM
THEY'VE UPGRADED.
ARCHER: ANY HUMAN BIO-SIGNS?
T'POL:
NINE ON THE ARCTIC TRANSPORT.
THE READINGS ARE ERRATIC.
ARCHER:
CAN YOU DISABLE THEIR WEAPONS?
REED: I BELIEVE SO.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
REED: THEIR WEAPONS ARE DOWN.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE GOING TO WARP.
ARCHER: IS THERE ANYONE ALIVE
ON THE TARKALEAN SHIP?
T'POL: TWO BIO-SIGNS
ON THEIR UPPER DECK.
I'M READING
MINIMAL LIFE SUPPORT.
ARCHER: HOLD OUR POSITION.
GET A SHUTTLEPOD READY.
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE.
PHLOX: THE TARKALEANS
SHOULD LIVE,
BUT THE NANOPROBES
HAVE INFILTRATED
THEIR AUTONOMIC SYSTEMS.
THEIR RENAL GLANDS
HAVE BEEN REPLACED
WITH DEVICES LIKE THIS.
ESSENTIALLY, THESE INDIVIDUALS
ARE BEING TRANSFORMED
INTO SOME SORT
OF CYBERNETIC HYBRID.
ARCHER: YOU SAID THE HUMAN
BIO-SIGNS WERE ERRATIC.
T'POL: IT'S LIKELY
THE RESEARCHERS ARE
GOING THROUGH
A SIMILAR TRANSFORMATION.
ARCHER:
CAN YOU REMOVE THE NANOPROBES?
PHLOX: NOT SURGICALLY.
THESE DEVICES ARE MULTIPLYING AT
AN EXTRAORDINARY RATE.
I COULD NEVER EXTRACT THEM ALL.
I'M ATTEMPTING TO SLOW
THEIR PROGRESS
WITH A MODIFIED RETROVIRUS,
BUT SO FAR I HAVEN'T
BEEN VERY SUCCESSFUL.
T'POL: PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
ISOLATE THEM
IN THE DECON CHAMBER.
PHLOX:
IF YOU DO THAT, I WON'T BE ABLE
TO TREAT THEM AS EFFECTIVELY.
I DON'T BELIEVE
THEY'RE A DANGER TO THE CREW.
ARCHER: I'M NOT SO SURE.
I'LL HAVE MALCOLM
POST A GUARD.
KEEP ME UPDATED.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
T'POL: I'VE CONTACTED TARKALEA.
I TOLD THEM WE'RE DOING
EVERYTHING WE CAN
FOR THEIR CREWMEN.
ARCHER: ANY SIGN
OF THE TRANSPORT?
T'POL: NOTHING.
ARCHER: THERE WAS SOMETHING
FAMILIAR ABOUT ALL THIS,
BUT I COULDN'T PUT
MY FINGER ON IT
UNTIL I FOUND THIS SPEECH
ZEFRAM COCHRANE
MADE 89 YEARS AGO.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
I READ EVERYTHING
I COULD ABOUT HIM.
IT TOOK ME A WHILE,
BUT I FINALLY FOUND IT
IN THE DATABASE.
HE WAS GIVING A COMMENCEMENT
ADDRESS AT PRINCETON
WHEN HE STARTED
TO TALK ABOUT
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED
DURING FIRST CONTACT.
HE MENTIONED A GROUP
OF CYBERNETIC CREATURES
FROM THE FUTURE
WHO TRIED TO STOP
HIS FIRST WARP FLIGHT
WHEN HE WAS LIVING IN MONTANA.
HE SAID THEY WERE DEFEATED
BY A GROUP OF HUMANS
WHO WERE ALSO FROM THE FUTURE.
T'POL:
AS I RECALL, COCHRANE WAS FAMOUS
FOR HIS IMAGINATIVE STORIES.
HE WAS ALSO KNOWN TO BE
FREQUENTLY INTOXICATED.
ARCHER:
NO ONE TOOK HIM SERIOUSLY,
AND HE RECANTED THE WHOLE THING
A FEW YEARS LATER.
BUT YOU HAVE TO ADMIT,
THERE ARE SIMILARITIES.
T'POL:
HE SAID THEIR ULTIMATE GOAL WAS
TO ENSLAVE THE HUMAN RACE.
ARCHER: IF HE WAS RIGHT,
THEY MIGHT BE HEADING BACK
TO THEIR HOMEWORLD
SO THEY CAN TRY AGAIN.
[TARKALEAN GROANING]
[TARKALEAN GASPING]
TARKALEAN: WHO ARE YOU?!
PHLOX: MY NAME IS PHLOX.
I'M A PHYSICIAN.
YOU ARE ABOARD A STARSHIP.
WE RESPONDED
TO YOUR DISTRESS CALL.
TARKALEAN:
WHAT DID YOU DO TO ME?!
PHLOX: YOUR VESSEL WAS ATTACKED.
I'M DOING MY VERY BEST
TO TREAT YOU.
[TARKALEAN GROANING]
PHLOX: I'M GOING TO SEDATE HIM.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
ARCHER: DOCTOR?
PHLOX.
WHAT HAPPENED?
PHLOX: WE WERE ATTACKED.
I'VE BEEN INFECTED
WITH THE NANOPROBES.
ONE OF THE ALIENS
INJECTED ME
WITH SOME SORT OF TUBULES.
REED: CAPTAIN.
THEY LEFT THROUGH HERE.
ARCHER:
SEAL OFF THE MAINTENANCE SHAFTS.
POST TEAMS
AT EVERY ACCESS POINT.
WHEN YOU FIND THEM, PUT THEM
IN DECON, MAXIMUM SECURITY.
REED: AYE, SIR.
PHLOX: USE EXTREME CAUTION,
LIEUTENANT.
THEIR PHYSICAL STRENGTH
HAS BEEN ENHANCED.
IT'S CRITICAL THAT YOU
DON'T LET THEM TOUCH YOU.
PHLOX:
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN INFECTED.
GUARD: THANKS, DOCTOR.
ARCHER: STAY HERE IN CASE
THERE ARE ANY MORE PROBLEMS.
GUARD: UNDERSTOOD.
ARCHER: CALL THE BRIDGE
IF YOU NEED ANYTHING.
PHLOX: ACTUALLY, IT'S, UH,
FEEDING TIME
FOR MY EDOSIAN SLUGS.
THEY'RE QUITE PARTIAL
TO BOILED ROOTLEAF.
I USUALLY PICK SOME UP
FROM THE GALLEY,
BUT UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES--
ARCHER: I'LL HAVE IT
BROUGHT DOWN.
TUCKER: THEY'VE MODIFIED MOST OF
THE PRIMARY SYSTEMS--
ENGINES, HULL PLATING.
THESE LOOK LIKE
WEAPONS NODES.
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO GUESS
WHAT THIS THING'S FOR.
ARCHER: DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
THEY'VE ENHANCED
THE AFT PLATING YET.
IF WE CAN PUNCH THROUGH IT HERE,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO KNOCK OUT
THIS E.P.S. MANIFOLD,
TAKE DOWN THEIR MAIN POWER.
TUCKER: ONE OR TWO TORPEDOES
OUGHT TO DO IT.
T'POL: T'Pol to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: I'VE LOCATED
THE TRANSPORT
ON LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
THEY'RE TRAVELING AT WARP 4.8.
ARCHER: How far are they?
T'POL:
LESS THAN TWO LIGHT-YEARS.
ARCHER: I NEED YOU TO COAX
A LITTLE MORE POWER
OUT OF THE ENGINES.
TUCKER: I'LL GIVE IT A SHOT.
ARCHER: TRAVIS, LAY IN A COURSE,
WARP 4.9.
TRAVIS: Aye, sir.
TUCKER: THEY'VE DOUBLED
THEIR TOP SPEED
IN LESS THAN 12 HOURS.
ARCHER: LET'S HOPE THEY
DIDN'T HAVE TIME
TO UPGRADE THEIR WEAPONS.
REED: STOP WHAT YOU'RE DOING!
I'LL FIRE IF I HAVE TO.
I SAID, STEP AWAY.
MAXIMUM SETTING.
FALL BACK.
REED: REED TO THE BRIDGE.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
REED: THEY'RE IN MAINTENANCE
SHAFT "C," JUNCTION 12.
THEY APPEAR TO BE
MODIFYING SYSTEMS.
ARCHER: WHAT'S IN THAT JUNCTION?
T'POL: WARP PLASMA REGULATORS.
ARCHER: CAN YOU STOP THEM?
REED: OUR WEAPONS WERE USELESS.
THEY'RE EQUIPPED WITH
SOME KIND OF ENERGY SHIELDING.
TRAVIS: SIR, OUR WARP FIELD'S
DESTABILIZING.
T'POL: IT'S THEM.
ARCHER: ISN'T THERE AN OUTER
HATCH IN THAT JUNCTION?
T'POL: YES.
ARCHER: MALCOLM, GET OUT
OF THAT SECTION AND SEAL IT OFF.
REED: UNDERSTOOD.
COME ON, GO.
ARCHER: TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
REED: WE'RE CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: SUB-COMMANDER.
T'POL: THE JUNCTION'S EMPTY.
ARCHER: CLOSE THE HATCH
AND REPRESSURIZE.
MALCOLM, I WANT YOU
TO WORK WITH TRIP.
FIND OUT WHAT THEY
WERE DOING IN THERE.
REED: AYE, SIR.
ARCHER: RESUME COURSE AND SPEED.
T'POL: YOU HAD NO CHOICE.
HOSHI: ROOM SERVICE.
PHLOX: WHAT'S THIS?
HOSHI:
ROOTLEAF LETTUCE FOR YOUR SLUGS,
VULCAN SANDWORMS FOR THE BAT,
AND ANGEL HAIR PASTA
FOR THE SHIP'S PHYSICIAN.
PHLOX: IT'S BEST IF I AVOID
FOOD FOR THE TIME BEING.
HOSHI: YOU NEED TO KEEP UP
YOUR STRENGTH.
PHLOX: IF I EAT, MY CELLULAR
METABOLISM WILL ACCELERATE.
THE NANOPROBES
COULD SPREAD FURTHER.
HOSHI: WELL, IT'S RIGHT HERE
IF YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND.
PHLOX: WHY ARE YOU WEARING
A PHASE PISTOL?
HOSHI:
OH, IT'S LIEUTENANT REED'S IDEA.
IF YOU COME NEAR ME,
I'M SUPPOSED TO SHOOT YOU.
PHLOX: I HOPE YOU'LL USE
THE STUN SETTING.
HOSHI:
IT'S GONNA BE A FEW HOURS
BEFORE WE CATCH UP
WITH THAT TRANSPORT.
I'M SURE THAT CAPTAIN ARCHER
WOULDN'T MIND IF I STAYED
FOR A LITTLE WHILE,
KEPT YOU COMPANY.
PHLOX: I APPRECIATE THE OFFER,
BUT IT MAY NOT BE SAFE
TO BE NEAR ME RIGHT NOW.
HOSHI: I'M ARMED, REMEMBER?
YOU'VE LOOKED AFTER ME
MORE TIMES THAN I CAN COUNT.
I WANT TO RETURN THE FAVOR.
PHLOX: THE TECHNOLOGY COULD
ASSERT ITSELF AT ANY MOMENT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
WILL HAPPEN IF IT DOES.
I UNDERESTIMATED
THESE NANOPROBES ONCE.
I DON'T INTEND TO MAKE
THE SAME MISTAKE TWICE.
HOSHI: DO YOU MIND IF I FEED
YOUR ANIMALS BEFORE I GO?
[ANIMAL SQUEAKING]
TUCKER: THEY DID A REAL
NUMBER ON THESE CIRCUITS.
IT COULD TAKE DAYS
TO GET ALL THIS JUNK OUT.
REED: WHAT DO YOU THINK
THEY WERE DOING HERE?
TUCKER: I DON'T KNOW.
BUT THEY ALMOST OVERLOADED
THE PLASMA REGULATORS.
DOESN'T MAKE
A WHOLE LOT OF SENSE.
WHY BLOW UP THE SHIP
IF YOU'RE STILL ON IT?
HAND ME THAT, WILL YOU?
REED: THAT SHIELDING
OF THEIRS WAS IMPRESSIVE.
WE MIGHT AS WELL HAVE BEEN
FIRING HOLOGRAPHIC BULLETS.
TUCKER: TOO BAD YOU DIDN'T
GET A CLOSER LOOK.
THAT KIND OF TECHNOLOGY
COULD COME IN HANDY.
REED: THERE'S GOT TO BE A WAY
TO GET THROUGH THOSE
SHIELDS WITH PHASE PISTOLS.
IF I CROSS-POLARIZE
THE POWER CELLS,
IT MIGHT INCREASE
THE PARTICLE YIELD.
I'LL BE IN THE ARMORY.
ARCHER: COFFEE WITH CREAM.
T'POL: I BELIEVE CREWMAN
CUNNINGHAM IS IN THE GALLEY
IF YOU'D LIKE SOMETHING ELSE.
ARCHER: THIS WILL BE FINE.
IS THIS SEAT TAKEN?
T'POL: PLEASE.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
T'POL: LIEUTENANT REED
INFORMED ME
THAT YOU PLAN TO DISABLE
THE TRANSPORT WHEN WE FIND IT.
ARCHER: HE THINKS WE CAN
KNOCK OUT THE POWER SYSTEMS
WITHOUT CAUSING
TOO MUCH DAMAGE.
T'POL: SO YOU STILL INTEND
TO RESCUE THE HUMANS?
ARCHER:
THAT'S THE GENERAL IDEA.
T'POL: IF THEY'VE
ALREADY BEEN TRANSFORMED,
THAT COULD BE DIFFICULT.
ARCHER: I WANT TO TAKE
THESE PEOPLE HOME--
THE HUMANS AND THE TARKALEANS--
NO MATTER WHAT STATE THEY'RE IN.
T'POL: THERE ARE 29 LIFE-FORMS
ON THAT TRANSPORT.
IT'S LOGICAL TO ASSUME
THEY'VE ALL BEEN INFECTED.
WE COULD ENDANGER "ENTERPRISE"
IF THEY'RE BROUGHT ABOARD.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD RECONSIDER.
ARCHER: ARE YOU SAYING
WE SHOULDN'T GO AFTER THAT SHIP?
T'POL: I'M SAYING WE DESTROY IT.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
PHLOX: Phlox to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
PHLOX: Would you please
come to sick bay?
ARCHER: ON MY WAY.
I'M NOT READY
TO DECLARE THEM A LOST CAUSE.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
PHLOX:
BETTER THAN I ANTICIPATED.
THE NANOPROBES SEEM TO BE
HAVING TROUBLE
WITH MY IMMUNE SYSTEM.
BUT THEY'RE PERSISTENT
LITTLE FELLOWS.
IT WON'T BE LONG
BEFORE THEY ADAPT.
ARCHER: ANY PROGRESS FINDING
A TREATMENT?
PHLOX: POSSIBLY.
I'VE BEEN ATTEMPTING
TO TREAT THE INFECTION
AS IF IT WERE, UH,
WELL, AN INFECTION.
THEN IT SUDDENLY OCCURRED TO ME
THIS ISN'T A BIOLOGICAL PROBLEM.
I NEED TO THINK LIKE
AN ENGINEER, NOT A PHYSICIAN.
I EXTRACTED SEVERAL
OF THE DEVICES
AND SUBJECTED THEM
TO DIFFERENT FORMS OF RADIATION.
THEIR INTRAMOLECULAR
PROCESSORS
APPEAR TO BE VULNERABLE
TO OMICRON PARTICLES.
BUT IF ONE
OF THE NANOPROBES SURVIVES,
IT WILL START TO MULTIPLY AGAIN,
SO I'LL NEED TO PROGRAM
A RATHER EXCESSIVE DOSE.
THE SIDE-EFFECTS
WILL NOT BE PLEASANT,
TO SAY THE LEAST.
YOU MAY WANT TO KEEP THIS
IN THE EVENT I'M UNSUCCESSFUL.
ARCHER: WHAT IS IT?
PHLOX: A CURE OF SORTS.
IT CONTAINS A NEURAL TOXIN
THAT WILL TERMINATE
MY SYNAPTIC FUNCTIONS
WITHIN A MATTER OF SECONDS.
ARCHER: AREN'T YOU JUMPING
THE GUN A LITTLE?
PHLOX: I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF TURNING INTO ONE OF THOSE
CYBERNETIC CREATURES.
REED: INCREASE POWER
ANOTHER FIVE MEGAJOULES.
FIRE.
KEEP IT GOING.
INCREASE TO SEVEN MEGAJOULES.
TRY EIGHT.
NINE.
THE DENSITY'S HOLDING.
BRING IT UP TO 10.
THAT SHOULD DO IT.
WE'LL REACH THAT TRANSPORT
IN LESS THAN AN HOUR.
LET'S MODIFY AS MANY OF THESE
AS WE CAN.
T'POL: THE VESSEL'S MASS
HAS INCREASED BY 3%.
REED:
THEY'VE IMPROVED THEIR DEFENSES
SINCE WE LAST SAW THEM.
TRAVIS: THEY'RE ACCELERATING.
WARP 4.96.
TRAVIS: 4.98.
ARCHER: INCREASE SPEED.
TRAVIS: WE'RE CLOSING.
ARCHER:
TARGET THAT E.P.S. MANIFOLD.
TRAVIS:
THEY'RE DROPPING TO IMPULSE.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
HOSHI:
THEY'RE SENDING A TRANSMISSION,
SOME KIND
OF ACTIVATION SEQUENCE.
ARCHER: BLOCK IT.
HOSHI: I CAN'T.
TUCKER: TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE.
THESE CYBERNETIC CIRCUITS
JUST LIT UP LIKE
A CHRISTMAS TREE.
T'POL: THEY'RE DISRUPTING
OUR PLASMA NETWORK.
MAIN POWER IS FAILING.
REED: WE'RE LOSING WEAPONS.
ARCHER: THEY SET US UP.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
HOSHI: THEY'RE HAILING US,
AUDIO ONLY.
ARCHER: THIS IS CAPTAIN--
COMPUTERIZED VOICE:
YOU WILL BE ASSIMILATED.
RESISTANCE IS FUTILE.
REED:
HULL PLATING'S DOWN TO 81%.
ARCHER:
TRIP, WE COULD USE WEAPONS.
TUCKER:
IT'S GONNA BE A FEW MINUTES.
REED: PLATING'S
DOWN ANOTHER 12%.
ARCHER: IS THE TRANSPORTER
STILL ONLINE?
REED: FOR THE MOMENT.
ARCHER: THEN YOU'RE WITH ME.
T'POL: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: I'M COUNTING ON YOU
TO PULL US OUT OF THERE.
[INDISTINCT ALIEN VOICES]
GUARD: DOCTOR?
PHLOX: I'VE PROGRAMMED
THE IRRADIATION SEQUENCE,
BUT I'LL NEED YOU TO ACTIVATE
IT ONCE THE CHAMBER'S SEALED.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS PRESS THIS.
REED:
I'VE DOUBLED THE PARTICLE YIELD.
IT MAY TAKE A FEW SECONDS
TO RECHARGE AFTER EACH SHOT.
ARCHER: PUT US
AS CLOSE AS YOU CAN
TO THEIR E.P.S. MANIFOLD.
ENGINEER: AYE, SIR.
TRAVIS: HULL PLATING'S AT 23%.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
ARCHER: THIS WAS ONE
OF THE RESEARCHERS.
REED: WAS?
ARCHER:
LOOK AT THESE BIO-SIGNS.
THEY'RE NOT HUMAN ANYMORE.
REED: SIR.
[ALARM]
HOSHI: WE'VE BEEN BOARDED.
SIX BIO-SIGNS, "C" DECK.
T'POL: ALERT SECURITY.
BRIDGE TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
TUCKER: GO AHEAD.
T'POL: HOW MUCH LONGER?
TUCKER: I THINK I'VE ISOLATED
ONE OF THE POWER RELAYS.
STAND BY. AAH!
REED: ANOTHER HUMAN?
ARCHER: SAME AS THE OTHERS.
[REED GAGGING]
[SCANNER BEEPING]
ARCHER: THAT'S IT.
REED: CAPTAIN!
TRAVIS: WE'VE LOST HULL PLATING.
HOSHI:
THEY'RE CUTTING INTO THE HULL.
"E" DECK, STARBOARD FOREQUARTER.
T'POL: EVACUATE THAT SECTION.
ARCHER: THEY'VE ADAPTED.
HURRY, MALCOLM.
ARCHER TO "ENTERPRISE."
STAND BY TRANSPORTER.
T'POL: ACKNOWLEDGED.
ARCHER: NOW.
TUCKER: TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE.
T'POL: Go ahead.
TUCKER: THE ALIEN CIRCUITS
ARE LOSING POWER.
T'POL: DO WE HAVE WEAPONS?
TUCKER: THEY'RE COMING
ONLINE NOW.
ARCHER: REPORT.
T'POL: OUR ENGINES
AND WEAPONS ARE BACK ONLINE.
THE TRANSPORT'S BEEN DISABLED.
SO HAS THE ALIEN CIRCUITRY.
DID YOU FIND
THE RESEARCH TEAM?
ARCHER: THERE ISN'T
ANYONE ON THAT SHIP
WE CAN HELP ANYMORE.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
REED: SIR, SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING ON THE TRANSPORT.
THEIR SYSTEMS
ARE BEING RESTORED.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
ARCHER: TARGET THEIR WARP CORE.
HIT THEM WITH
EVERYTHING WE'VE GOT.
GET ME ADMIRAL FORREST.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
MARCH 1, 2153.
REPAIRS TO THE SHIP
ARE UNDERWAY,
AND WE'VE RESUMED OUR
PREVIOUS HEADING AT LOW WARP.
DR. PHLOX IS CONFIDENT
HE'LL MAKE A COMPLETE RECOVERY.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO BE IN BED?
PHLOX: I'M MERELY
CATCHING UP ON SOME PAPERWORK.
NOTHING TOO STRENUOUS,
I ASSURE YOU.
IT'S VITAL TO KEEP
THE MIND OCCUPIED
DURING THE HEALING PROCESS.
ARCHER: THEY SAY DOCTORS
MAKE THE WORST PATIENTS.
PHLOX: CAPTAIN, THERE'S
SOMETHING YOU SHOULD KNOW.
I HAD
A RATHER STRANGE EXPERIENCE
WHILE I WAS INFECTED.
I BELIEVE I WAS
CONNECTED WITH THE ALIENS,
POSSIBLY THROUGH
SOME FORM OF TELEPATHY.
ARCHER: DO YOU THINK
THEY WERE TRYING
TO COMMUNICATE WITH YOU?
PHLOX: NOT PRECISELY.
IT FELT AS THOUGH I WAS PART
OF A GROUP CONSCIOUSNESS.
T'POL: YOU WERE UNDER
EXTRAORDINARY PHYSICAL STRESS.
YOU MAY HAVE IMAGINED IT.
PHLOX: IT SEEMED QUITE REAL.
I COULDN'T UNDERSTAND
MOST OF WHAT I WAS HEARING,
BUT I GOT
THE DISTINCT IMPRESSION
THEY WERE TRYING TO SEND
A SUBSPACE MESSAGE.
THEY TRANSMITTED
A NUMERICAL SEQUENCE.
I HEARD IT OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
THE COMPUTER ANALYZED
PHLOX'S NUMBERS.
THEY'RE PULSAR FREQUENCIES
WITH GEOMETRIC
LIGHT-YEAR MEASUREMENTS.
T'POL: SPATIAL COORDINATES.
ARCHER: THEY TOLD THEIR
HOMEWORLD HOW TO FIND EARTH.
T'POL: DID YOU LEARN
WHERE THE MESSAGE WAS SENT?
ARCHER: SOMEWHERE DEEP
IN THE DELTA QUADRANT.
T'POL: THEN I DOUBT THERE'S
ANY IMMEDIATE DANGER.
IT WOULD TAKE AT LEAST 200 YEARS
FOR A SUBSPACE MESSAGE
TO REACH THE DELTA QUADRANT,
ASSUMING IT'S RECEIVED AT ALL.
ARCHER: SOUNDS TO ME LIKE WE'VE
ONLY POSTPONED
THE INVASION UNTIL WHAT,
THE 24th CENTURY?