T'POL: IT COULD BE
A PHANTOM READING.
BACKGROUND RADIATION.
ARCHER: EVEN YOUR
SCIENTISTS HAVE CONFIRMED
THE EXISTENCE OF DARK MATTER.
T'POL: NEVER IN SUCH
DENSE CONCENTRATIONS.
ARCHER: THAT'S THE POINT.
IF IT REALLY
IS A DARK-MATTER NEBULA,
WE'D BE THE FIRST
TO DIRECTLY OBSERVE ONE.
T'POL:
EVEN WITH MODIFIED SENSORS,
THERE WOULDN'T BE MUCH TO SEE.
ARCHER:
I'VE HEARD OF VULCAN EXPERIMENTS
WHERE THEY WERE ABLE
TO EXCITE DARK MATTER
BY BOMBARDING IT
WITH METREON PARTICLES.
T'POL: THOSE TESTS INVOLVED
VERY SMALL QUANTITIES.
THIS STRUCTURE IS NEARLY
10 MILLION KILOMETERS
IN DIAMETER.
ARCHER: COULD YOU RIG
SOME KIND OF SPATIAL CHARGES?
SOMETHING THAT'D SPREAD
THE METREON PARTICLES
OVER A WIDER AREA?
TUCKER: AH, IF I CAN, IT
SHOULD PUT ON A HELL OF A SHOW.
HOSHI:
SORRY TO INTERRUPT, CAPTAIN.
IT'S ADMIRAL FORREST.
ARCHER:
GET TO WORK ON THOSE CHARGES.
TUCKER: AYE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER:
THIS IS GOOD TIMING, ADMIRAL.
WE JUST PICKED UP SOME VERY
INTERESTING SENSOR READINGS.
FORREST: I'M AFRAID I'VE
GOT SOME BAD NEWS, JON.
IT'S A.G.
HE WAS BACK ON MOUNT McKINLEY.
THERE WAS AN ACCIDENT.
HE WAS KILLED.
I'M SORRY.
SINGER: ♪ IT'S BEEN
A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE
MY HEART WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA
BEND OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
TUCKER:
YOU'VE GOT SIX SPATIAL CHARGES.
I RIGGED THEM MYSELF.
ARCHER: WHAT ARE THEIR RANGES?
TUCKER:
IF THERE'S ANY DARK MATTER
WITHIN 500 KILOMETERS,
YOU'LL KNOW.
ARCHER: THANKS.
TUCKER: YOU SURE
YOU DON'T WANT SOME COMPANY?
ARCHER: IF THIS NEBULA EXISTS,
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT EFFECT
IT COULD HAVE ON THE SHUTTLEPOD.
TUCKER: ALL THE MORE REASON
TO BRING YOUR ENGINEER ALONG.
ARCHER: NOT THIS TIME, TRIP.
TUCKER:
I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
ARCHER: ALL THE CLOSE CALLS
HE HAD FLYING WARP TRIALS.
AND HE GETS HIMSELF KILLED
CLIMBING MOUNT McKINLEY.
T'POL: I'VE BROUGHT
SOME SENSOR ENHANCEMENTS.
ARCHER: THANKS.
T'POL: WE'LL FIND THEM
USEFUL IN MAPPING THE NEBULA.
IF IT'S THERE.
ARCHER: WE?
T'POL: THIS IS
A SCIENTIFIC MISSION.
IT'S ONLY LOGICAL TO BRING
YOUR SCIENCE OFFICER.
ARCHER: I'D PREFER
TO HANDLE THIS MYSELF.
T'POL: COMMANDER TUCKER
OBVIOUSLY DIDN'T REMIND YOU
THAT STARFLEET REGULATIONS
PROHIBIT THE CAPTAIN FROM
LEAVING THE SHIP UNACCOMPANIED.
WE SHOULD REACH
THE EDGE OF THE PHENOMENON
IN 2 HOURS, 46 MINUTES.
I CAN PASS THE TIME
BY MEDITATING,
BUT IF YOU'D PREFER TO TALK...
ARCHER: GO AHEAD AND MEDITATE.
T'POL: WOULD YOU LIKE
TO JOIN ME?
YOU'VE SEEMED QUITE UNSETTLED
SINCE YOUR CALL
FROM ADMIRAL FORREST.
ARCHER: I'M FINE.
T'POL:
COMMANDER TUCKER WAS RELUCTANT
TO DISCUSS IT AS WELL,
THOUGH HE DID MENTION
AN OLD COLLEAGUE HAD DIED.
ARCHER: A STARFLEET CAPTAIN.
A.G. ROBINSON.
I WOULDN'T BE OUT HERE
IF IT WEREN'T FOR HIM.
T'POL: I'M SOMEWHAT FAMILIAR
WITH STARFLEET HISTORY.
I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF A CAPTAIN ROBINSON.
ARCHER: I'M SURE THERE'S
A PARAGRAPH ABOUT HIM
IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
WE WERE
IN THE NX TEST PROGRAM...
TRYING TO BREAK
THE WARP 2 BARRIER.
THERE WERE JUST A FEW OF US.
GARDNER, DUVALL, A.G., AND ME.
WE ALL WANTED THE FIRST FLIGHT.
AND I WAS COCKY ENOUGH TO
THINK I'D BE THE ONE TO GET IT.
[DOOR CHIMES]
FORREST: COME IN.
ARCHER: SORRY
I'M LATE, COMMODORE.
I CAME STRAIGHT
FROM THE TEST BAY.
FORREST: AT EASE, COMMANDER.
I HEARD YOU GOT THE WARP
REACTOR UP TO 90% TODAY.
ARCHER: 92.
SIR...
YOU DIDN'T CALL ME HERE
TO ASK ABOUT AN ENGINE TEST.
WE ALL KNOW THE ASSIGNMENT'S
ABOUT TO BE HANDED OUT.
I'M GUESSING THIS IS
EITHER REALLY GOOD NEWS OR--
FORREST: WE'RE GOING
WITH COMMANDER ROBINSON.
ARCHER: A.G. IS A FINE PILOT.
FORREST:
IT WASN'T AN EASY DECISION.
YOU'LL BE BACKUP.
ARCHER: SOUNDS GOOD.
YOU KNOW, I'VE SPENT MORE TIME
IN THE SIMULATOR THAN ANYONE.
IF I CAN DO ANYTHING
TO HELP A.G. PREPARE FOR--
FORREST: JON.
IT'S YOUR FATHER'S ENGINE.
I KNOW HOW IMPORTANT
THIS WAS TO YOU.
ARCHER: THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING TO ME
IS THAT WE SUCCEED.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE?
FORREST: NO, COMMANDER.
DISMISSED.
[MID-TEMPO JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
ARCHER: THANKS, RUBY.
RUBY: YOU ALL RIGHT?
ARCHER: SURE. WHY?
RUBY: THE LAST TIME
YOU HAD THIS MUCH TO DRINK
WAS THE DAY CAROLINE
MOVED TO NEW BERLIN.
MY GUESS IS FORREST
GAVE OUT THE ASSIGNMENT TODAY.
ARCHER: SHERLOCK HOLMES
HAS NOTHING ON YOU.
RUBY: THEY'LL NEED A PILOT
FOR THE NEXT FLIGHT.
ARCHER: YOU REMEMBER
WHAT BUZZ ALDRIN SAID
WHEN HE STEPPED ON THE MOON?
RUBY: NO.
ARCHER: NOBODY DOES.
BECAUSE ARMSTRONG WENT FIRST.
MAN: BEST MAN.
DIFFERENT MAN: CONGRATULATIONS.
DIFFERENT MAN: HEAR! HEAR!
MEN: GOOD JOB.
ARCHER: CONGRATULATIONS.
ROBINSON: YOU MEAN THAT?
ARCHER: OF COURSE NOT.
I'M WAITING FOR FORREST
TO REALIZE
WHAT A HORRIBLE MISTAKE HE MADE.
[LAUGHTER]
UNTIL THEN,
LET ME BUY YOU A DRINK.
ROBINSON: NO, I'LL BUY YOU ONE.
A CONSOLATION PRIZE.
ROBINSON: TWO MORE, LEO.
LEO: HERE YOU GO.
ARCHER:
TO COMMANDER A.G. ROBINSON.
WE ALL WORKED HARD
TO GET THIS FLIGHT,
BUT IN THE END,
THE BEST PILOT WON.
JUST ASK HIM.
[LAUGHTER]
TO A.G.
MEN AND WOMEN: TO A.G.
MAN: TO A.G. YES.
MEN: TO A.G.
WOMAN: HEAR! HEAR!
ARCHER: TAKE IT EASY, COMMANDER.
YOU'RE DUE IN THE SIMULATOR
AT 0700.
FIRST FLIGHT'S IN TWO WEEKS.
ROBINSON: YOU KNOW WHY YOU
DIDN'T GET THIS ASSIGNMENT.
ARCHER: I BET
YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME.
ROBINSON: YOU TRIED TOO HARD.
YOU DID EVERYTHING BY THE BOOK.
YOU BURNED THE MIDNIGHT OIL
IN THAT SIMULATOR.
18-, 20-HOUR DAYS.
YOU SHUT EVERYTHING
AND EVERYONE OUT OF YOUR LIFE
JUST SO YOU COULD BE THE FIRST.
ARCHER: AND?
ROBINSON:
YOU STILL DON'T UNDERSTAND.
STARFLEET DOESN'T JUST WANT
A GREAT PILOT.
THEY WANT A GREAT CAPTAIN.
T'POL: YOU SAID CAPTAIN ROBINSON
WAS A CLOSE FRIEND.
ARCHER: THAT'S RIGHT.
T'POL: FROM WHAT YOU'VE TOLD ME,
YOUR RELATIONSHIP SEEMED
ADVERSARIAL.
ARCHER: ONLY ONE OF US WAS GOING
TO GET TO FLY THAT SHIP.
NOTHING WRONG WITH
A LITTLE HEALTHY COMPETITION.
T'POL: HE DID HAVE A POINT.
IT DOES TAKE MORE
THAN PILOTING ABILITY
TO COMMAND A STARSHIP.
ARCHER: I AGREE.
T'POL: FORTUNATELY,
YOU SEEM TO HAVE DEVELOPED
THE NECESSARY SKILLS.
ARCHER: WAS THAT A COMPLIMENT?
T'POL: AN OBSERVATION.
I ASSUME CAPTAIN ROBINSON'S
FLIGHT WAS SUCCESSFUL?
ARCHER: NOT EXACTLY.
HE WAS LUCKY TO COME OUT OF IT
IN ONE PIECE.
ROBINSON: NX Control,
I thought we built a warp ship
so we could go to warp.
ARCHER: MAINTAIN YOUR ORBIT.
WE'RE TRYING
TO RUN DOWN A PROBLEM
WITH THE STABILIZATION
PROTOCOLS.
ROBINSON:
I just saw Italy go by again.
If this is gonna take
much longer,
maybe you could send up
some food.
ARCHER: WHAT CAN I GET YOU?
ROBINSON:
HOW ABOUT SOME OF THOSE
DEEP-FRIED MUSHROOMS
FROM THE 602?
ARCHER: I'LL SEND
RUBY UP TO TAKE YOUR ORDER.
OFFICIAL: WE ARE CLEAR
ON THE STABILIZATION PROTOCOLS.
RESTART COUNTDOWN AT 30 SECONDS.
ARCHER: GOOD NEWS, A.G.
I JUST GOT WORD
FROM THE POWERS THAT BE
THAT YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
ROBINSON: ACKNOWLEDGED.
WSP IS NOMINAL.
A.P.U.s ARE GOOD.
ARCHER: WARP FIELD
INITIALIZATION IN 20 SECONDS.
ROBINSON: I'M BREAKING ORBIT.
AT LEAST THE THRUSTERS WORK.
ARCHER: HMM.
ROBINSON: I DID GET A LITTLE
VARIANCE ON THE RCS.
ARCHER: WE NOTICED THAT HERE.
DO YOU WANT TO BRING HER BACK
TO THE GARAGE?
ROBINSON: NOT ON YOUR LIFE.
OFFICIAL:
WE'VE GOT A STABLE WARP FIELD.
ARCHER:
NX CONTROL TO NX-ALPHA.
YOU HAVE PERMISSION
TO GO TO WARP.
ROBINSON:
SEE YOU IN A FEW LIGHT-YEARS.
ARCHER: WARP 1.
1.5.
THAT LITTLE BUMP YOU JUST FELT
WAS WARP 2.
CONGRATULATIONS.
NOW LET'S SEE
IF YOU CAN GET IT UP TO 2.1.
ROBINSON:
SHE'S GETTING A LITTLE SHAKY.
Are you sure you got that
stabilization problem
ironed out?
OFFICIAL:
FIELD INTEGRITY'S DOWN TO 20%.
VULCAN: THE WARP FIELD
WON'T HOLD.
ARCHER: A.G., WE'RE GETTING
SOME PRETTY UNUSUAL
TELEMETRY DOWN HERE.
WE NEED YOU TO GO SUBLIGHT
UNTIL WE GET IT SORTED OUT.
[ALARM IN CONTROL ROOM]
[ALARM IN NX-ALPHA]
ARCHER: Did you hear me?
ROBINSON: I'M AT 2.1.
I THINK I CAN GET
A LITTLE MORE OUT OF HER.
ARCHER: Negative. Abort.
WARP 2.15.
FORREST: THIS IS FORREST.
DROP TO IMPULSE.
THAT'S AN ORDER!
ARCHER: 2.2.
ROBINSON:
THE FIELD'S COLLAPSING!
ARCHER: A.G., you've got
to get out of there.
OFFICIAL: WE'VE LOST TELEMETRY.
ARCHER: NX-CONTROL
TO NX-ALPHA, COME IN.
A.G.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
T'POL: THE PARTICLE DENSITY
IS INCREASING.
ARCHER: WE SHOULD BE ENTERING
THE NEBULA.
T'POL: THE READINGS
COULD BE MISLEADING.
ARCHER: AS DR. PHLOX WOULD SAY,
"OPTIMISM."
T'POL: OPTIMISM DOESN'T ALTER
THE LAWS OF PHYSICS.
ARCHER: TIME TO PUT TRIP'S
CHARGES TO THE TEST.
THREE SECONDS.
ANYTHING?
WE NEED TO MOVE DEEPER
INTO THE NEBULA...
IF IT EXISTS.
T'POL: WHAT HAPPENED?
ARCHER: THE FIELD EMISSIONS
ON THE CHARGES
COULD HAVE BEEN TOO LOW.
OR MAYBE WE'RE JUST
ON A WILD GOOSE CHASE.
T'POL: I WAS REFERRING
TO CAPTAIN ROBINSON--
HIS TEST FLIGHT.
ARCHER: HE MADE THE RECORD BOOKS
FOR BEING THE FIRST PERSON
TO DEPLOY AN ESCAPE POD AT WARP.
BUT HE LOST
ONE OF TWO NX PROTOTYPES.
NEARLY DERAILED
THE ENTIRE PROGRAM.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
ROBINSON: A LITTLE SHAKY.
TRUST ME, YOU DON'T WANT TO PASS
THROUGH THE WARP BARRIER
IN ONE OF THOSE.
SHE'D MAKE A NICE ADDITION
TO THE STARFLEET MUSEUM.
FORREST: WHAT WENT WRONG?
ROBINSON: I'M NOT SURE, SIR.
THE CLOSER I GOT TO 2.2,
THE MORE TROUBLE I HAD
KEEPING THE FIELD STABLE.
ARCHER:
YOU WERE ORDERED TO ABORT.
ROBINSON:
THE ABORT CALL WAS PREMATURE.
WE HAD SOME INSTABILITY
ON THE PREVIOUS TESTS,
BUT IT ALWAYS SETTLED DOWN.
VULCAN: YOUR ENGINE DESIGN
IS OBVIOUSLY UNSOUND.
TUCKER: THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT ENGINE.
FORREST: YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO ADD, LIEUTENANT...?
TUCKER: TUCKER, SIR.
I'M ON CAPTAIN JEFFERIES'
ENGINEERING TEAM.
WE'VE NEVER PUMPED
THIS MUCH ANTIMATTER
THROUGH THE INJECTORS BEFORE.
IT'S GONNA TAKE US A LITTLE
TIME TO GET THE INTERMIX RIGHT.
VULCAN:
THAT'S PRECISELY THE POINT.
YOUR PROGRAM
IS MOVING TOO QUICKLY.
TUCKER: JUST BECAUSE IT TOOK YOU
A HUNDRED YEARS TO CRACK WARP 2
DOESN'T MEAN
IT'LL TAKE US THAT LONG.
FORREST: LIEUTENANT!
TUCKER: SORRY, SIR.
ARCHER: HE'S RIGHT.
THIS IS A NEW ENGINE.
IT'S BOUND TO HAVE
A FEW BUGS TO WORK OUT.
VULCAN: THOSE "BUGS"
JUST SCATTERED YOUR SHIP
ACROSS 5,000 KILOMETERS
OF SPACE
AND NEARLY KILLED YOUR PILOT.
ROBINSON:
WE'RE NOT GOING TO GET ANYWHERE
WITHOUT TAKING SOME RISKS.
FORREST: I KNOW WHERE YOU
STAND ON THIS, COMMANDER.
ARCHER: WE'VE GOT A LOT OF DATA
TO ANALYZE
BEFORE WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
WE SHOULD BE GRATEFUL
WE ONLY LOST THE SHIP.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING,
INDISTINCT TALKING]
TUCKER: CYRUS.
RUBY: CYRUS?
ARCHER: WHO'S CYRUS?
TUCKER: IT WAS
MY GREAT-GRANDFATHER'S NAME.
RUBY: KEEP TRYING, TUCKER.
TUCKER: CHESTER.
HOW ABOUT ROSALIE
IF IT'S A GIRL?
COME ON. GIVE ME A HINT.
SHE'S HAD NAMES FOR HER KIDS
PICKED OUT SINCE SHE WAS 10.
SAYS SHE'LL MARRY
THE FIRST MAN TO GUESS THEM.
ARCHER:
WHAT'S YOUR NAME, LIEUTENANT?
TUCKER: CHARLES TUCKER, SIR.
BUT EVERYBODY CALLS ME TRIP.
ARCHER: TRIP?
MY DAD'S CHARLES TUCKER,
AND SO WAS HIS DAD,
AND THAT MAKES ME THE THIRD,
SO, TRIPLE--TRIP.
ARCHER:
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP TODAY
WITH OUR VULCAN FRIENDS, TRIP.
MY FATHER WOULD HAVE
APPRECIATED IT.
TUCKER: I DON'T GET IT.
IT'S--IT'S LIKE
THEY WANT US TO FAIL.
FORREST:
I GAVE UP TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
THE VULCANS A LONG TIME AGO.
ARCHER: COMMODORE.
FORREST: AT EASE.
MAY I?
ARCHER: OF COURSE.
[TUCKER CLEARS THROAT]
TUCKER: CAN I, UH...
BUY YOU A DRINK, SIR?
FORREST:
IT'S THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
AFTER THAT OUTBURST TODAY.
TUCKER: I'M SORRY, SIR.
I-I DIDN'T MEAN TO...
FORREST:
I'LL HAVE A BEER, MR. TUCKER.
IT'S BEEN AWHILE
SINCE I'VE BEEN IN HERE.
I SEE IT HASN'T CHANGED MUCH.
ARCHER: IS THERE SOMETHING
ON YOUR MIND, SIR?
FORREST:
I CAME HERE TO TELL YOU...
AT THE URGING OF
THE VULCAN ADVISORY COUNCIL,
THAT STARFLEET COMMAND
HAS DECIDED
TO PUT THE NX PROGRAM ON HOLD.
ARCHER: FOR HOW LONG?
FORREST: INDEFINITELY.
RUBY: GENTLEMEN?
TUCKER: ONE BEER.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
INDEFINITELY?
FORREST: THEY WANT TO GO
BACK TO THE DRAWING BOARD, JON,
DEVELOP A NEW ENGINE
FROM SCRATCH.
ARCHER: WE HAVE AN ENGINE
THAT WORKS NOW.
IF WE START OVER,
IT'LL BE DECADES
BEFORE WE GET INTO DEEP SPACE.
FORREST:
STARFLEET'S MADE ITS DECISION.
TUCKER: PERMISSION
TO SPEAK FREELY, SIR?
IT'S YOUR FATHER'S
ENGINE, HIS LIFE'S WORK.
YOU CAN'T LET THEM DO THIS.
ROBINSON: BOURBON, STRAIGHT UP.
ARCHER: I SUPPOSE YOU HEARD.
ROBINSON: THIS IS REALLY
GOING TO THROW A WRENCH
IN MY CAREER PLANS.
THANKS.
RUBY: LAST CALL. ANYTHING ELSE?
ROBINSON: I'LL HAVE ANOTHER.
ARCHER:
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN ALL DAY?
ROBINSON: DEBRIEFING.
AFTER THE FLIGHT SURGEONS
WERE DONE WITH ME,
I GOT HAULED IN FRONT
OF THE STARFLEET SENIOR STAFF
AND THE VULCANS.
TUCKER: WHAT DID YOU TELL THEM?
ROBINSON: WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THE SUBSPACE FIELD DESTABILIZED
AT WARP 2.2.
PRIMARY FLIGHT CONTROLS FAILED,
RESULTING IN THE LOSS
OF THE VEHICLE.
TUCKER:
AREN'T YOU FORGETTING SOMETHING?
ROBINSON: WHAT?
TUCKER:
THE POSSIBILITY OF PILOT ERROR.
ROBINSON: I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN YOUR OPINION, LIEUTENANT.
ARCHER: YOU SHOULD BE.
THE VULCANS HAVE BEEN
LEANING ON STARFLEET FOR YEARS
TO REIN IN THIS PROGRAM.
YOU WALKED IN THERE TODAY,
RULED OUT PILOT ERROR,
AND TOLD THEM
JUST WHAT THEY WANTED TO HEAR--
"OUR ENGINE DOESN'T WORK."
ROBINSON: SORRY TO BE
THE BEARER OF BAD NEWS, ARCHER,
BUT IT DOESN'T WORK.
TUCKER: THE ENGINE'S SOUND.
WE JUST NEED MORE TIME
TO BALANCE THE INTERMIX.
ROBINSON:
WE NEED MORE THAN TIME.
ARCHER: I AGREE.
WE NEED A PILOT
WHO LISTENS TO ORDERS.
IF YOU'D ABORTED,
WE'D STILL HAVE A SHIP
AND PROBABLY ANOTHER CHANCE.
ROBINSON: ANOTHER
CHANCE TO WHAT, GET KILLED?
ARCHER:
AT THE FIRST SIGN OF TROUBLE,
YOU SHOULD'VE THROTTLED DOWN.
ROBINSON: IT WOULDN'T HAVE
MADE A DAMN BIT OF DIFFERENCE.
ARCHER:
I GUESS WE'LL NEVER FIND OUT.
ROBINSON:
YOU WEREN'T IN THAT COCKPIT.
ARCHER: THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH THAT SHIP!
ROBINSON: THERE'S PLENTY WRONG.
YOU JUST REFUSE TO SEE IT.
ARCHER: WHAT THE HELL'S
THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
ROBINSON: EVERY TIME THERE'S
A PROBLEM WITH THIS PROJECT,
YOU BLAME IT ON PILOT ERROR
OR GRAVITATIONAL ANOMALIES
OR SOME TECHNICAL MALFUNCTION.
WELL, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO FACE THE TRUTH THIS TIME
BECAUSE THERE'S NOTHING LEFT
TO POINT A FINGER AT.
YOUR FATHER
DESIGNED A LOUSY ENGINE.
RUBY: THAT'S ENOUGH!
DO SOMETHING!
TUCKER: COME ON, COME ON.
BREAK IT UP! BREAK IT UP!
OFFICIAL: EASY, A.G. GUYS!
RUBY: YOU THINK THIS
IS GONNA GET EITHER OF YOU
ANY CLOSER TO WARP 5?
T'POL:
THE FIGHT WAS INTERRUPTED?
ARCHER: NOT BEFORE
I GOT TWO BRUISED RIBS
AND A CRACKED MOLAR.
T'POL:
I SUPPOSE WE'LL NEVER KNOW.
WHO WOULD HAVE WON.
[BEEPING]
T'POL:
MAIN POWER IS FLUCTUATING.
ARCHER: THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
AUXILIARY'S KICKING IN.
T'POL: THERE WAS A SURGE
IN THE E.P.S. GRID.
ARCHER:
WE MUST BE GETTING CLOSE.
TRIP SAID THE DARK MATTER
MIGHT AFFECT
THE SHUTTLE'S SYSTEMS.
HE'LL BE HAPPY TO HEAR
HE WAS RIGHT.
T'POL: IT WAS
PROBABLY NOTHING MORE
THAN A SIMPLE MALFUNCTION.
ARCHER: I DON'T THINK SO.
OUR PRELAUNCH CHECKS
WERE ALL FINE.
SOMETHING ELSE
CAUSED THAT SURGE.
T'POL: I'M NOT DETECTING
ANY DARK MATTER.
ARCHER:
HAVE A LITTLE FAITH, T'POL.
T'POL: EVEN IF YOU'RE RIGHT,
IT MAY BE DANGEROUS TO PROCEED.
ANOTHER SURGE
COULD DISABLE LIFE SUPPORT.
ARCHER:
ONE THING I LEARNED FROM A.G.--
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA GET ANYWHERE
WITHOUT TAKING RISKS.
T'POL:
YOU OBVIOUSLY ADMIRED THIS MAN.
ARCHER: QUITE A BIT.
T'POL:
AND YET HE CRACKED YOUR MOLAR?
[ARCHER CHUCKLES]
ARCHER: HUMANS CAN HAVE FUNNY
WAYS OF FORMING FRIENDSHIPS.
T'POL: TO SAY THE LEAST.
ARCHER:
HE WOULD HAVE LOVED IT OUT HERE.
TOO BAD HE NEVER GOT THE CHANCE.
GOD KNOWS HE EARNED IT.
T'POL: I THOUGHT YOU SAID
HE WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR NEARLY ENDING THE PROGRAM.
ARCHER: HE WAS ALSO RESPONSIBLE
FOR GETTING IT BACK ON COURSE...
WITH A LITTLE HELP
FROM ME AND TRIP.
ARCHER: I SEE YOU'RE NOT LOSING
ANY TIME.
ROBINSON: WE'RE DONE FLYING.
NO USE HANGING AROUND.
HERE YOU GO.
ARCHER:
I'M NOT CLEARING OUT JUST YET.
ROBINSON: SUIT YOURSELF.
ARCHER:
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU WERE
SAYING LAST NIGHT
ABOUT MY FATHER'S ENGINE.
ROBINSON: LOOK,
I WAS OUT OF LINE.
ARCHER: YOU WERE RIGHT.
I WANTED TO SEE THIS THING
FLY SO BADLY,
IT KEPT ME
FROM BEING OBJECTIVE.
ROBINSON: THAT'S GOOD OF YOU
TO ADMIT, BUT...
IT DOESN'T REALLY MATTER NOW.
ARCHER: IT MAY.
I GOT MY HANDS ON THE TELEMETRY
FROM YOUR FLIGHT.
IT LOOKS LIKE TUCKER WAS RIGHT
ABOUT THE INTERMIX,
BUT I THINK WE CAN
COMPENSATE FOR IT.
ROBINSON: YOU HEARD FORREST.
THE PROGRAM
IS ON HOLD INDEFINITELY.
ARCHER:
WE CAN TAKE THIS TO STARFLEET.
MAKE A CASE
TO GET OFF THE GROUND AGAIN.
ROBINSON:
WHAT ABOUT THE VULCANS?
THEY'LL LOOK AT YOUR DATA
AND SAY WE NEED
TO RUN COMPUTER SIMULATIONS
FOR ANOTHER 10 YEARS
TO PROVE THAT YOU'RE RIGHT.
ARCHER: COMMODORE FORREST
WILL BACK US UP.
ROBINSON: FORREST ANSWERS
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
IT'S OUT OF HIS HANDS.
ARCHER:
EVEN IF HIS TWO SENIOR PILOTS
INSIST THAT THIS SHIP CAN FLY?
IF THE THREE OF US
GO IN THERE TOGETHER,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO CHANGE THEIR MINDS.
YOU JUST WENT FASTER THAN
ANY HUMAN BEING EVER HAS.
AND NOW YOU'RE GONNA WALK AWAY?
LET THEM PUT THE SHIP
IN MOTHBALLS
WHEN WE'RE SO CLOSE
TO BREAKING WARP 3?
YOU'RE ALWAYS TALKING ABOUT
TAKING RISKS.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT TO LOSE?
ROBINSON: IF YOU WANT
TO CONVINCE THE VULCANS,
YOU'LL HAVE TO DO A LOT BETTER
THAN SHOWING THEM A BUNCH
OF ANTIMATTER CALCULATIONS.
ARCHER:
I'M OPEN TO SUGGESTIONS.
ROBINSON:
WE ONLY LOST ONE SHIP.
WE STILL HAVE ONE LEFT.
ARCHER:
THEY'LL NEVER GIVE US CLEARANCE.
ROBINSON: CAN YOU THINK OF
A BETTER WAY TO PROVE IT'LL FLY?
YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT
TAKING RISKS?
YOU'RE A GREAT PILOT.
MAYBE AS GOOD AS ME.
BUT YOU'RE NEVER GONNA
GET OUT INTO DEEP SPACE
BY PLAYING IT SAFE.
WHEN THE FIRST
WARP 5 STARSHIP IS BUILT,
ITS CAPTAIN WON'T BE ABLE
TO CALL HOME
EVERY TIME HE NEEDS
TO MAKE A DECISION.
HE WON'T BE ABLE TO TURN
TO THE VULCANS
UNLESS HE DECIDES
TO TAKE ONE WITH HIM.
[BEEPING]
ARCHER: WE SHOULD BE 20,000
KILOMETERS INSIDE THE NEBULA.
LET'S LOAD UP TWO MORE CHARGES.
T'POL: THE HISTORY
OF YOUR EARLY WARP FLIGHTS
IS WELL DOCUMENTED.
BUT I'VE NEVER READ ANYTHING
ABOUT TWO STARFLEET PILOTS
STEALING THE WARP 3 PROTOTYPE.
ARCHER: IT WASN'T THE KIND OF
THING STARFLEET COMMAND
WANTED TO ADVERTISE.
DON'T YOU BELIEVE ME?
T'POL: I HAVE NO DOUBT
IT HAPPENED,
THOUGH I FIND IT
DIFFICULT TO BELIEVE
YOU HAD TO BE CONVINCED
TO PARTICIPATE.
ARCHER: WELL...
YOU DIDN'T KNOW ME THEN.
I WAS A LITTLE MORE BY THE BOOK.
[BEEPING]
T'POL: THE PARTICLE DENSITY
HAS NEARLY DOUBLED.
SHALL WE TRY AGAIN?
T'POL: PERHAPS WE
SHOULD HEAD BACK.
ARCHER:
WE STILL HAVE TWO MORE CHARGES.
LET'S KEEP LOOKING.
T'POL: WAS YOUR TEST FLIGHT
SUCCESSFUL?
ARCHER:
PROMISE YOU WON'T PUT THIS
INTO THE VULCAN DATABASE?
WE DECIDED ON A NIGHT LAUNCH.
TUCKER: I'VE ROUTED
THE INTERMIX CONTROLS
TO THE ENGINEERING STATION.
IF IT BECOMES UNSTABLE, YOU'LL
BE ABLE TO ADJUST IT MANUALLY.
ARCHER: THANKS.
TUCKER: IF I CAME ALONG,
I COULD MONITOR
THE ANTIMATTER FLOW.
ARCHER: I'LL KEEP AN EYE ON IT.
TUCKER: YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
YOUR HANDS FULL.
ARCHER: WE NEED YOU DOWN HERE.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'LL GET OUT THERE SOMEDAY.
IF I HAD MY OWN SHIP,
I'D SIGN YOU UP IN A SECOND.
TUCKER:
I'M GONNA HOLD YOU TO THAT.
ARCHER: THANKS, TRIP.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
NO RESPONSE
FROM THE AUXILIARY A.P.U.s.
ROBINSON: THAT'S BECAUSE
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN INSTALLED YET.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
ARCHER: HOW'S IT COMING, TRIP?
TUCKER: I'VE DISABLED
THE TRACKING SENSORS.
BUT I'LL NEED A MINUTE
TO DIVERT THE TELEMETRY.
ARCHER: How long?
TUCKER: DON'T WAIT FOR ME.
I'LL BE READY
BY THE TIME YOU BREAK ORBIT.
ARCHER: ACKNOWLEDGED.
ROBINSON:
NOT TOO LATE TO CALL THIS OFF,
HEAD OVER TO THE 602 FOR A BEER.
ARCHER: NOT ON YOUR LIFE.
ANYONE NOTICE WE'RE GONE YET?
TUCKER: Nah, as far
as they know,
the doors are closed
and the lights are out.
BUT NEW BERLIN
SHOULD BE PICKING YOU UP
IN ABOUT SIX MINUTES.
ROBINSON: BY THE TIME THEY
FIGURE OUT WHAT'S GOING ON,
WE'LL BE HALFWAY TO JUPITER.
[DOOR CHIMES]
FORREST: COME IN.
YOU'RE WORKING LATE.
OFFICIAL: WE JUST GOT A CALL.
NEW BERLIN'S DETECTED
THE NX-BETA.
FORREST: WHAT?
OFFICIAL: INTERNAL SENSORS SHOW
IT'S STILL IN THE HANGAR.
FORREST:
HAS ANYONE BOTHERED TO LOOK?
ARCHER: WARP FIELD IS STABLE.
SOMETHING WRONG?
ROBINSON: WHY DON'T YOU TAKE IT?
ARCHER: WHAT?
ROBINSON: I HAD THE LAST FLIGHT.
YOU'RE DUE UP.
BESIDES...
YOU COULD USE THE PRACTICE.
HOPE YOU AND TUCKER WERE RIGHT
ABOUT THAT INTERMIX.
ARCHER:
WE'RE ABOUT TO FIND OUT.
[BEEPS]
FORREST: This is Forrest.
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?
ARCHER: Just running
an engine test, sir.
FORREST: ARCHER?
TURN AROUND RIGHT NOW,
AND I'LL DO WHAT I CAN
to keep you out of
prison. If you--
[ROBINSON CUTS OFF TRANSMISSION]
ARCHER?
PERFECT.
ROBINSON: THAT'S WARP 2.
TUCKER: HERE WE GO AGAIN.
I'M READING FLUCTUATIONS
IN THE INTERMIX.
ARCHER: We see it.
[ALARM]
TUCKER: YOUR WARP FIELD'S
DESTABILIZING!
ARCHER: WARP 2.15.
YOU BETTER GET THAT INTERMIX
LOCKED DOWN
'CAUSE I'M NOT BACKING OFF
TILL I BREAK YOUR RECORD.
ARCHER: YOU GOT IT?
ROBINSON: ALMOST.
OFFICIAL:
COME WITH US, LIEUTENANT.
TUCKER: NX-BETA, DO YOU READ?
ARCHER:
NX-Beta to Commodore Forrest.
You might want to check
your sensors.
You'll see we're holding steady
at 2.5.
FORREST: CONGRATULATIONS.
NOW, GET THE HELL BACK HERE.
NOT ONLY WAS IT IN VIOLATION
OF A DIRECT ORDER,
IT WAS UTTERLY RECKLESS,
IRRESPONSIBLE,
AND MAYBE EVEN CRIMINAL.
ROBINSON: SIR--
FORREST:
I'M NOT DONE, COMMANDER!
YOU ARE BOTH SUSPENDED FROM DUTY
PENDING AN INQUIRY.
AND BY THE TIME
STARFLEET COMMAND
GETS THROUGH WITH YOU,
YOU'RE GONNA WISH
THAT YOU HAD NEVER COME BACK.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO REPRESENT
THE BEST
THAT STARFLEET HAS TO OFFER.
KEEPING THIS PROGRAM ON TRACK
IS HARD ENOUGH
WITHOUT OUR OWN OFFICERS
UNDERMINING IT.
WHAT DID YOU THINK
THAT THIS STUNT OF YOURS
WOULD ACCOMPLISH?
THAT JUST BECAUSE YOU DIDN'T
GET YOURSELVES KILLED
THAT WE'D IGNORE
THE DATA WE'VE COLLECTED,
THE TESTING WE'VE DONE,
THE RECOMMENDATIONS
OF THE VULCAN ADVISORY COUNCIL?
ROBINSON: IF WE FOLLOW
ALL THEIR RECOMMENDATIONS,
WE'LL NEVER MAKE IT
INTO DEEP SPACE.
VULCAN: NO ONE IS SUGGESTING
THAT YOUR WARP PROGRAM
BE DISMANTLED,
ONLY THAT STARFLEET PROCEED
WITH MORE RESTRAINT.
ROBINSON:
GET LIEUTENANT TUCKER IN HERE.
ASK ANY ENGINEER ON THE PROJECT.
THEY'LL TELL YOU
THIS SHIP CAN FLY.
ARCHER AND I JUST PROVED IT.
WE'RE READY TO GO NOW.
VULCAN: THAT'S NOT
YOUR DECISION TO MAKE.
ARCHER: WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
IT'S NOT YOURS EITHER.
YOU'RE RIGHT, SIR.
WE WERE RECKLESS.
WE KNEW THERE'D BE CONSEQUENCES.
WE KNEW WE'D PROBABLY
BE THROWN OUT OF STARFLEET.
ROBINSON:
YOU MAY HAVE BEEN RIGHT.
ARCHER:
A.G. AND I MAY NEVER FLY AGAIN.
BUT IT'S A SMALL SACRIFICE
TO MAKE
IF IT KEEPS THIS PROJECT GOING.
WE DIDN'T BUILD THIS ENGINE
TO MAKE TEST RUNS
AROUND JUPITER.
WE BUILT IT TO EXPLORE!
IF MY FATHER WERE ALIVE TODAY,
HE'D BE STANDING HERE ASKING,
"WHAT THE HELL
ARE WE WAITING FOR?"
T'POL: YOU OBVIOUSLY WEREN'T
DISMISSED FROM STARFLEET.
THEY MUST HAVE FOUND
YOUR ARGUMENT CONVINCING.
CONVINCING ENOUGH.
WE MANAGED TO AVOID
A COURT-MARTIAL,
BUT THEY GROUNDED US
FOR THREE MONTHS.
T'POL:
STILL, THE NX PROGRAM CONTINUED.
ARCHER: EVENTUALLY.
THE VULCANS HAD US RUN
EVERY SIMULATION THEY COULD
THINK OF FOR OVER A YEAR
BEFORE THEY FINALLY ADMITTED
THE ENGINE WOULD PROBABLY WORK.
EIGHT MONTHS AFTER THAT,
DUVALL BROKE WARP 3
IN THE NX-DELTA.
FIVE YEARS LATER, WE LAID
THE KEEL FOR ENTERPRISE.
YOU KNOW THE REST.
[BEEPING]
T'POL: THE PARTICLE DENSITY
HAS INCREASED AGAIN.
ARCHER: I'D HATE TO SEE THOSE
LAST TWO CHARGES GO TO WASTE.
ARCHER: ANYTHING ON SENSORS?
T'POL: IT APPEARS SO.
FASCINATING.
THIS DATA WILL CERTAINLY
CAUSE A DEBATE
AT THE SCIENCE DIRECTORATE.
ARCHER: T'POL...
COME UP AND LOOK AT THIS
A MINUTE.
T'POL: I HAVE TO MONITOR
THE QUANTUM FIELD.
ARCHER:
LET THE SENSORS DO IT.
THAT'S WHY A.G. AND I
WORKED SO HARD TO GET OUT HERE.
T'POL: CAPTAIN ROBINSON CLEARLY
WANTED TO COMMAND
"ENTERPRISE" AS MUCH AS YOU DID.
ARCHER: HE WASN'T ALONE.
BUT BY THE END,
A.G. AND I WERE
THE ONLY TWO CANDIDATES LEFT.
THEY MADE THE FINAL SELECTION
6 MONTHS BEFORE WE LAUNCHED.
MAYBE I JUST GOT LUCKY.
THANKS.
RUBY: CONGRATULATIONS, CAPTAIN.
ROBINSON: TO JONATHAN ARCHER,
FIRST SKIPPER
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE"...
AND ONE LUCKY S.O.B.
ARCHER: LUCK HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
ROBINSON:
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN TALENT.
[ROBINSON CHUCKLES]
I'M JUST WAITING
FOR FORREST TO REALIZE
WHAT A HORRIBLE MISTAKE HE MADE.
[ARCHER LAUGHING]
ROBINSON: STILL...
THEY COULD'VE DONE A LOT WORSE.
ANYWAY, I'D RATHER WAIT
FOR THE NX-02.
LET YOU MAKE ALL THE MISTAKES
SO I'LL HAVE
AN EASIER TIME OF IT.
ARCHER: TO THE FIRST SKIPPER
OF THE NX-02.
ROBINSON: GOT TO GO.
I'M CATCHING A SHUTTLE
TO ALICE SPRINGS AT 0600.
MORE SURVIVAL TRAINING.
GOOD NIGHT, RUBY.
GOOD LUCK, JON.
HEY.
I'LL SEE YOU OUT THERE.
T'POL: CAPTAIN...
WE SHOULD START BACK IF WE'RE
GOING TO MAKE OUR RENDEZVOUS.
ARCHER: RIGHT.
TUCKER:
WELCOME BACK. HOW'D IT GO?
T'POL: YOUR CHARGES
WERE EFFECTIVE.
TUCKER: WAS IT A GOOD SHOW?
ARCHER:
YOU SHOULD'VE BEEN THERE.
TUCKER: I'LL REMEMBER
TO ASK YOU NEXT TIME.
T'POL: I BELIEVE THERE'S
A HUMAN CUSTOM
THAT SAYS WHEN YOU DISCOVER
SOMETHING OF MERIT,
YOU EARN THE RIGHT TO NAME IT.
ARCHER:
WHAT WOULD YOU SUGGEST?
THE T'POL-ARCHER NEBULA?
T'POL: I WAS THINKING
THE ROBINSON NEBULA
WOULD BE MORE APPROPRIATE.