ARCHER: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
MARCH 21, 2153.
AFTER THREE DAYS EXPLORING
AN UNINHABITED PLANET,
COMMANDER TUCKER AND I
HAVE BEEN CALLED BACK
TO "ENTERPRISE"
TO GREET AN UNEXPECTED VISITOR.
MAYBE YOU WERE LIGHT-HEADED
FROM THE ALTITUDE.
TUCKER: I DIDN'T SLIP.
THAT OVERHANG GAVE WAY
THE MOMENT I PUT MY FOOT ON IT.
ARCHER: I WALKED ON THE SAME
ROCKS YOU DID.
TUCKER:
WELL, MAYBE YOU LOOSENED THEM.
YOU DO WEIGH A FEW KILOS
MORE THAN I DO.
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER: REPORT.
REED: IT DROPPED OUT OF WARP
30 MINUTES AGO
AND THE PILOT SENT
A BRIEF AUDIO MESSAGE.
HE INSISTED ON SPEAKING
WITH YOU RIGHT AWAY.
ARCHER: ANY IDEA WHAT HE WANTS?
REED: HE WOULDN'T SAY.
BUT I DID MANAGE TO
FIND HIS SHIP DESIGN
IN THE VULCAN DATABASE.
IT'S TELLARITE.
ARCHER: T'POL'S MENTIONED THEM.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
THIS IS JONATHAN ARCHER
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
SKALAAR: YOU CAN START
BY TELLING ME
WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE.
ARCHER: I DIDN'T GET YOUR NAME.
SKALAAR: CAPTAIN SKALAAR
OF THE TELLARITE
MINING CONSORTIUM.
ARCHER:
WE'RE STUDYING THIS PLANET.
I HAVE THREE SCIENCE TEAMS
ON THE SURFACE.
WE'RE ALSO HERE
FOR A LITTLE SHORE LEAVE.
SKALAAR: SHORE LEAVE?
ARCHER: VACATION.
IT'S BEEN AWHILE SINCE WE'VE HAD
A CHANCE TO RELAX.
SKALAAR:
IN THAT CASE, I RECOMMEND
YOU VISIT THE EQUATORIAL RANGE.
THE VIEW FROM
THE NORTH SUMMIT IS INSPIRING.
ARCHER: YOU'VE BEEN HERE BEFORE?
SKALAAR: MANY TIMES.
I PREFER TO THINK OF IT
AS MY OWN PERSONAL RETREAT.
YOU MUSTN'T LEAVE
UNTIL YOU'VE EXPERIENCED
THE HYDROTHERMAL POOLS
OF REN-GHAM. MMM...
ARCHER: WHERE ARE THEY?
SKALAAR: THE POLAR ISLAND CHAIN,
227 KILOMETERS
FROM THE SOUTHERN TIP
OF THE RYKOS SHORELINE.
LOOK FOR THE PYROCLASTIC
DEBRIS FIELD,
THEN FOLLOW THE LAVA TUBES...
TUCKER: SOUNDS LIKE
WE COULD USE A GUIDE.
SKALAAR: I'D BE HAPPY
TO SHOW YOU.
ARCHER:
SURE WE'RE NOT INTRUDING?
SKALAAR: NOT AT ALL.
I'LL MEET YOU
AT YOUR STARBOARD DOCKING PORT.
I'LL HELP YOU PLAN
YOUR SHORE LEAVE.
ARCHER: T'POL SAYS THEY'RE
NOT THE MOST AGREEABLE SPECIES.
APPARENTLY THEY ENJOY
A GOOD ARGUMENT.
IT'S CONSIDERED A SPORT
ON THEIR PLANET.
TUCKER:
WELL, I'VE GOT AN OLD GIRLFRIEND
THIS GUY MIGHT LIKE TO MEET.
[ARCHER LAUGHS]
SINGER:
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE
NOT GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[BEEPING]
HOSHI: I'M PICKING UP
WEAPONS FIRE ON "E" DECK.
STARBOARD AIRLOCK.
REED: SEND A SECURITY TEAM.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
TRAVIS: THE TELLARITE SHIP'S
TRYING TO UNDOCK
WITH THE SEALS LOCKED.
REED:
ENGAGE THE EMERGENCY CLAMPS.
TRAVIS: HE'S GOING TO WARP.
REED: PURSUIT COURSE.
TRAVIS: HE'S DISABLED
OUR STARBOARD NACELLE.
WE CAN'T FOLLOW HIM, SIR.
REED: GET THOSE TEAMS UP
FROM THE SURFACE.
TUCKER: We're having trouble
isolating his signature.
He must have done something
to mask it.
T'POL: HOW LONG
UNTIL WE HAVE WARP DRIVE?
TUCKER: LESS THAN AN HOUR.
T'POL: I'm on my way
to the bridge.
TUCKER: ACKNOWLEDGED.
PHLOX: I'M AFRAID
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE
FOR THE MOMENT.
WE BROUGHT A STOWAWAY WITH US--
A RATHER UNUSUAL MICROBE.
T'POL: IS IT CONTAGIOUS?
PHLOX: I'LL HAVE TO RUN
SOME MORE TESTS.
TO BE SAFE, WE SHOULD
BOTH GO THROUGH DECON.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I ASKED YOU A QUESTION.
AAH!
SKALAAR: I'D STAY CLEAR
OF THOSE EMITTERS IF I WERE YOU.
THE VERY LATEST TECHNOLOGY.
I INSTALLED THEM LAST MONTH.
ARCHER:
I DOUBT THIS SHIP OF YOURS
WILL BE A MATCH
FOR "ENTERPRISE."
SKALAAR: I'VE TAKEN
APPROPRIATE COUNTERMEASURES.
WE WON'T BE SEEING
ANY MORE OF YOUR STARSHIP.
ARCHER: I WANT TO KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE TAKING ME.
MY CREW'S NOT GONNA GIVE UP
UNTIL THEY FIND ME.
IF YOU TAKE ME BACK,
I'D BE WILLING TO FORGET
THIS EVER HAPPENED.
SKALAAR:
YOU CAN EITHER BE QUIET
OR SPEND THE REST
OF THIS TRIP UNCONSCIOUS.
WHICH DO YOU PREFER?
PHLOX: HMM.
THIS MICROBE IS MORE RESILIENT
THAN I THOUGHT.
IT DOESN'T SEEM TO BE VULNERABLE
TO THETA RADIATION.
T'POL: PERHAPS YOU CAN
INCREASE THE DOSAGE.
PHLOX:
THAT WOULDN'T BE ADVISABLE.
WE'D BOTH SUFFER
PERMANENT CELLULAR DAMAGE.
T'POL: THERE MUST BE
SOMETHING ELSE YOU CAN TRY.
PHLOX: DECON GEL "E"
MAY NEUTRALIZE THE MICROBE.
BUT, UH, IT WILL BE
SEVERAL HOURS
BEFORE WE KNOW
IF IT'S EFFECTIVE.
T'POL:
I CAN'T STAY HERE SEVERAL HOURS.
PHLOX: YOU HAVE LITTLE CHOICE.
THIS ORGANISM APPEARS
TO BE INFECTIOUS,
AND HUMANS WOULD BE FAR MORE
VULNERABLE TO IT
THAN YOU OR I.
COMMANDER TUCKER
IS QUITE CAPABLE.
IF HE NEEDS YOUR HELP,
HE KNOWS WHERE TO FIND YOU.
FORTUNATELY, NO ONE ELSE
ON THE SURFACE
WAS EXPOSED TO THE MICROBE.
I SUSPECT YOU AND I
WERE CONTAMINATED
WHEN WE CLIMBED
INTO THE SECOND RAVINE.
CONSIDERING THE QUANTITY
OF FAUNA DOWN THERE,
I'M NOT AT ALL SURPRISED.
WE WERE PROBABLY
INFECTED
BY THE MARSUPIALS I FOUND.
T'POL:
I TOLD YOU TO LEAVE THEM ALONE.
PHLOX: THEIR SALIVA IS
A NATURAL ANTICOAGULANT.
I COULDN'T RETURN
TO THE SHIP WITHOUT A SAMPLE.
I COULD USE YOUR ASSISTANCE.
T'POL: I WASN'T AWARE
A CURTAIN WAS INSTALLED.
PHLOX:
NOT EVERYONE IS COMFORTABLE
WITH THE IDEA OF DISROBING
IN FRONT OF OTHERS.
T'POL:
AN ODD ATTITUDE FOR A PHYSICIAN.
PHLOX: IT'S A CHARACTERISTIC
OF DENOBULAN MALES.
WE'RE MORE INHIBITED
THAN OUR WOMEN.
IT'S, UH, WELL, LED TO A NUMBER
OF AWKWARD MOMENTS.
MY STARFLEET PHYSICAL
WAS AN EXPERIENCE
I NEVER HOPE TO REPEAT.
T'POL: IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND.
[BEEPING]
REED: THE SENSORS
ARE PICKING UP
A FAINT WARP SIGNATURE.
TUCKER:
CAN YOU GET A FIX ON IT?
REED: BEARING 071 MARK 32.
IT'S ERRATIC, BUT IT MATCHES
OUR TELLARITE FRIEND.
TUCKER: SET A COURSE.
MAXIMUM WARP.
KLINGON: You're speaking
on a secure channel.
SKALAAR: I'M TRYING
TO REACH CAPTAIN GOROTH.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
THAT I SPEAK WITH HIM.
KLINGON: We're attempting
to transfer you.
Stand by.
GOROTH: This is Goroth.
What do you want?
SKALAAR: I HAVE THE FUGITIVE.
GOROTH: He's in your custody?
SKALAAR: HE'S STANDING ABOUT
FIVE METERS FROM ME.
YOU'LL BE PLEASED TO KNOW
HE'S STILL ALIVE.
I'M BRINGING HIM
TO KRONOS AS WE AGREED.
GOROTH: No.
I'm transmitting
rendezvous coordinates.
Be there in two days.
SKALAAR: I TRUST YOU'LL HAVE
THE FULL PAYMENT.
GOROTH:
You'll get what was promised.
SKALAAR: PLEASURE DOING BUSINESS
WITH YOU, CAPTAIN.
AS ALWAYS.
ARCHER:
HOW MUCH ARE THEY PAYING YOU?
YOU MENTIONED
THE KLINGON HOMEWORLD, KRONOS.
I ASSUME THIS HAS
SOMETHING TO DO
WITH MY ESCAPING PRISON.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT I'M ACCUSED OF.
SKALAAR: YOU'RE RIGHT.
AND I DON'T CARE TO.
REED:
THE SIGNATURE'S HOLDING STEADY.
LOOKS LIKE HE'S ORBITING
A G-TYPE STAR.
TUCKER: GO TO TACTICAL ALERT.
REED: IT APPEARS TO BE
A BEACON OF SOME KIND.
IT'S GENERATING A WARP SIGNATURE
IDENTICAL TO THE TELLARITE'S.
TUCKER: A DECOY.
ANYTHING ON SENSORS?
WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO START ALL OVER.
REED: WE'RE GETTING
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE
FROM THAT DEVICE.
IT'S THROWING OFF OUR SCANS.
TUCKER: THEN GET RID OF IT.
REED: WITH PLEASURE, SIR.
ARCHER: I HAVE NO IDEA WHAT
THE KLINGONS ARE PAYING YOU.
BUT WHATEVER IT IS,
STARFLEET WILL DOUBLE IT.
SKALAAR: I DON'T TAKE BRIBES
FROM CRIMINALS.
ARCHER: I'M NOT A CRIMINAL.
SKALAAR: KLINGON JUDICIARY
SAYS THAT YOU ARE.
ARCHER: MY CRIME WAS HELPING
A SHIP FULL OF REFUGEES.
SKALAAR: WELL, THAT WAS
VERY NOBLE OF YOU.
YOU'LL THINK TWICE
BEFORE DOING THAT AGAIN.
[SKALAAR CHUCKLES]
ARCHER: IT'S PRETTY CLEAR
I'M NEVER GOING
TO GET THE CHANCE.
I WAS SENTENCED TO LIFE
IN PRISON ON RURA PENTHE.
EVER HEARD OF IT?
SKALAAR:
I'M FAMILIAR WITH RURA PENTHE.
ARCHER: THE MAGISTRATE
ISN'T GOING
TO BE SO LENIENT NEXT TIME.
I'LL PROBABLY BE EXECUTED.
SKALAAR: THAT'S NOT MY CONCERN.
ARCHER: YOU DON'T CARE
THAT YOU'RE SENDING
AN INNOCENT MAN TO HIS DEATH?
SKALAAR: I'VE CAPTURED DOZENS
OF FUGITIVES.
EVERY ONE OF THEM CLAIMED
TO BE AN INNOCENT MAN.
ARCHER: IF THE KLINGONS
WANTED THEM, THEY PROBABLY WERE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THIS!
SKALAAR: GOROTH ALREADY KNOWS
YOU'RE ABOARD.
IF I DON'T DELIVER YOU,
HE'LL OFFER A REWARD
FOR BOTH OF US.
I'VE LEARNED
NEVER TO CROSS A KLINGON.
ARCHER:
IT MUST BE DIFFICULT...
WORKING FOR PEOPLE LIKE THEM.
SKALAAR: I DON'T ANSWER
TO THOSE SAVAGES.
I WORK FOR MYSELF.
ARCHER: THAT'S NOT HOW IT LOOKS
FROM IN HERE.
SKALAAR: IF YOU KNEW
HOW MUCH THEY WERE PAYING ME,
YOU'D UNDERSTAND.
THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH YOU.
I'M SURE YOU'RE NOT
A BAD PERSON.
JUST AN UNLUCKY ONE.
[DEVICE WHIRRING]
T'POL: YOU ARE MAKING IT
DIFFICULT TO MEDITATE.
PHLOX: YOU'VE DEVELOPED
A SLIGHT FEVER.
AND I'M ALSO READING
ELEVATED DOPAMINE LEVELS.
THE MICROBE MAY BE AFFECTING
YOUR LIMBIC SYSTEM.
T'POL: I CAN'T CONCENTRATE
UNDER THESE CONDITIONS.
PHLOX:
I DON'T MEAN TO BE INTRUSIVE.
T'POL:
THE CAPTAIN'S BEEN ABDUCTED.
HE MAY EVEN BE DEAD.
MY PLACE IS ON THE BRIDGE.
PHLOX: SUB-COMMANDER.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
[T'POL BREATHING HEAVILY]
T'POL: OPEN IT!
PHLOX:
YOU'LL SPREAD THE INFECTION.
T'POL: I'LL GO TO MY QUARTERS!
IF I SEAL OFF
THE VENTILATION SYSTEM,
IT SHOULD MINIMIZE
THE RISK OF EXPOSING ANYONE.
PHLOX:
YOUR QUARTERS ARE ON "C" DECK.
BY THE TIME YOU REACH THEM,
YOU'LL CONTAMINATE
HALF THE SHIP.
T'POL: UNLOCK THIS DOOR.
I GAVE YOU A DIRECT ORDER.
PHLOX:
I'M SORRY, BUT I CAN'T OBEY IT.
T'POL:
I CAN HAVE YOU COURT-MARTIALED.
PHLOX: I DOUBT THAT VERY MU--
T'POL: OPEN IT!
I APOLOGIZE.
I AM HAVING TROUBLE
SUPPRESSING MY EMOTIONS.
PHLOX: WE'LL KNOW IN A FEW HOURS
WHETHER THE GEL IS WORKING.
UNTIL THEN
PERHAPS A MILD SEDATIVE
MAY HELP.
SKALAAR: THE KLINGONS
ARE PAYING 9,000 DARSEKS.
THAT'S MORE THAN ENOUGH
TO GET "TEZRA" BACK.
GAAVRIN:
YOU'RE NOT BEING REALISTIC.
SKALAAR: I ALREADY
HAVE THE HUMAN IN CUSTODY.
THE REWARD IS GUARANTEED.
GAAVRIN: YOU'VE MADE
THIS PROMISE BEFORE.
SKALAAR: IN TWO DAYS, YOU'LL SEE
I'M TELLING THE TRUTH.
GAAVRIN: EVEN IF YOU GET
THE MONEY, WHICH I DOUBT,
IT WOULDN'T CHANGE MY DECISION.
SKALAAR: DO YOU WANT TO SCRUB
PLASMA INJECTORS
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE?
I'M GIVING YOU A CHANCE TO...
OHH!
ARCHER: WHO'S TEZRA?
SKALAAR: "TEZRA'S" NOT A PERSON.
IT'S A CARGO SHIP.
FAR MORE IMPRESSIVE
THAN THIS ANTIQUE.
YOU'RE GOING TO USE THE REWARD
TO BUY YOUR SHIP BACK?
SKALAAR:
YOU'D BE WISE TO KEEP QUIET.
THE KLINGONS PAY ME THE SAME
WHETHER YOU'RE ALIVE OR DEAD.
[BEEPING]
A VESSEL'S APPROACHING.
I WOULDN'T GET TOO OPTIMISTIC.
IT'S NOT YOUR STARSHIP.
KAGO-DARR:
YOU HAVE SOMETHING I WANT.
SKALAAR: ALWAYS ONE STEP
BEHIND ME, EH, KAGO?
KAGO-DARR: DROP OUT OF WARP
AND SURRENDER THE PRISONER.
SKALAAR: WHY WOULD I DO THAT?
KAGO-DARR:
DON'T FORCE ME TO TAKE ACTION.
SKALAAR: GOROTH TOLD YOU
WHERE I WAS, DIDN'T HE?
KAGO-DARR: YOU HAD TWO MONTHS
TO FIND THE HUMAN.
GOROTH CONTACTED ME
BECAUSE YOU OBVIOUSLY
WEREN'T GOING TO SUCCEED.
YOU'RE INCOMPETENT!
SKALAAR: IF I WAS INCOMPETENT,
ARCHER WOULD BE ABOARD
YOUR SHIP, WOULDN'T HE?
KAGO-DARR: THE HUMAN...
NOW.
SKALAAR: OR WHAT?
YOU'LL DESTROY MY SHUTTLE?
CAN'T COLLECT ON ARCHER
IF HE'S A CLOUD OF VAPOR.
YOU MAY WANT TO HOLD ON
TO SOMETHING.
ARCHER: LET ME OUT.
I CAN HELP YOU.
SKALAAR:
YOU MUST THINK I'M A FOOL.
ARCHER: YOU CAN'T
MANEUVER THE SHIP
AND MAKE REPAIRS
AT THE SAME TIME.
I'M A PILOT!
LET ME TAKE THE HELM.
SKALAAR: IF YOU TRY TO ESCAPE...
THIS IS
THE WARP-FIELD REGULATOR,
THE IMPULSE THROTTLE.
ARCHER: NAVIGATION SENSORS?
SKALAAR: THERE.
THERE'S AN L-CLASS PLANET
IN THIS SYSTEM.
I'M TAKING US OUT OF WARP.
SKALAAR: WHAT?
ARCHER: WE CAN'T OUTRUN HIM,
BUT HE MAY NOT BE
ABLE TO NAVIGATE
AS WELL AS WE CAN
IN THE PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE.
SKALAAR:
THIS SHIP WASN'T DESIGNED
FOR THESE MANEUVERS.
WE'VE LOST THE AFT CANNONS.
ARCHER:
WHAT ABOUT FORWARD CANNONS?
SKALAAR: STILL ONLINE.
ARCHER: WHAT ARE THESE?
SKALAAR: SUBSPACE BEACONS.
THEY GENERATE
A FALSE WARP SIGNATURE.
I USED ONE OF THEM
TO EVADE YOUR VESSEL.
ARCHER: GET READY
TO LAUNCH THEM.
SKALAAR: WHAT GOOD WILL THAT DO?
ARCHER: HE'S FLYING ON SENSORS
JUST LIKE WE ARE.
HE'LL ONLY HAVE A 1 IN 3 CHANCE
OF TARGETING US.
SKALAAR: READY.
ARCHER: NOW.
WE KNOCKED OUT HIS ENGINE.
HE'S MAKING
AN EMERGENCY LANDING.
SKALAAR: DON'T CELEBRATE YET.
OUR REACTOR'S LEAKING.
THE WARP DRIVE'S OFF-LINE.
I'M NEVER GOING TO MAKE
THE RENDEZVOUS.
ARCHER: ISN'T THAT A SHAME?
SKALAAR: THE REACTOR
ALSO POWERS LIFE SUPPORT.
ARCHER:
THEN YOU'D BETTER GET TO WORK.
SKALAAR: IT CAN ONLY BE
ACCESSED FROM THE OUTER HULL.
ARCHER:
THEN WE SHOULD SET DOWN HERE.
SKALAAR:
BUT KAGO'S ON THE SURFACE.
ARCHER: WE'LL LAND
A THOUSAND KILOMETERS AWAY.
PHLOX: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
T'POL: YOU SAID WE'D NEED
ANOTHER TREATMENT.
PHLOX: NOT FOR THREE HOURS.
T'POL: IS THERE ANY HARM
IN STARTING NOW?
PHLOX: I CAN APPLY IT MYSELF.
THANK YOU.
PERHAPS YOU NEED
ANOTHER SEDATIVE.
T'POL: REST IS NOT WHAT I NEED.
PHLOX: SUB-COMMANDER,
THIS BEHAVIOR
IS HARDLY APPROPRIATE.
T'POL: MY NAME IS T'POL.
YOU DON'T FIND ME ATTRACTIVE?
PHLOX: OF COURSE I DO,
BUT THAT IS NOT THE ISSUE.
T'POL: I'M FAMILIAR WITH
DENOBULAN SEXUALITY.
I KNOW THAT YOUR MARRIAGES
AREN'T EXCLUSIVE.
PHLOX: YOU AND I ARE COLLEAGUES.
IT'S AGAINST REGULATIONS.
T'POL: STARFLEET REGULATIONS.
THERE'S NO REASON TO BE
RESTRAINED BY HUMAN MORALITY.
PHLOX: IT'S OBVIOUS
YOU'RE NOT WELL. PLEASE.
T'POL: YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE DENYING YOURSELF.
YOUR ENDORPHIN
AND HORMONAL LEVELS
ARE DANGEROUSLY HIGH.
T'POL: YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I'M NOT ILL.
PHLOX: THESE ARE HARDLY
NORMAL READINGS.
T'POL: THEY'RE NORMAL
FOR A VULCAN IN MY CONDITION.
PHLOX:
YOU KNOW WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
T'POL: IT'S NOT SOMETHING
WE DISCUSS WITH OTHERS.
PHLOX: I BELIEVE IT'S TIME
FOR YOU TO AMEND THAT POLICY.
YOU HAVE MY ASSURANCE
IT WILL REMAIN BETWEEN US.
T'POL: WE CALL IT THE PON FARR--
THE CYCLE OF MATING.
PHLOX: HAVE YOU GONE
THROUGH THIS BEFORE?
T'POL: IT'S NOT TIME.
PHLOX:
IT'S POSSIBLE THE INFECTION
ACTED AS A CATALYST.
T'POL:
WHAT CAUSED IT DOESN'T MATTER.
IF I DON'T MATE WITH A MALE--
VULCAN OR OTHERWISE--
I'LL DIE.
ARCHER: THAT SHIP YOU MENTIONED,
THE "TEZRA"...
SOUNDS PRETTY IMPORTANT TO YOU.
SKALAAR: MORE THAN YOU KNOW.
IF KAGO COLLECTS THE REWARD,
HE'LL PROBABLY WASTE IT
ON ORION SLAVE GIRLS.
NOT ME.
I'M GOING TO DO SOMETHING USEFUL
WITH IT.
ARCHER: I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU WANT A CARGO SHIP.
DOESN'T SEEM PRACTICAL
IN YOUR LINE OF WORK.
SKALAAR: YOU THINK
I'VE BEEN CHASING
FUGITIVES MY ENTIRE LIFE?
NO, ONCE I GET THE MONEY,
I'LL HAVE ENOUGH TO PAY OFF
THE IMPOUND FEES.
I'LL BE A FREIGHTER CAPTAIN
AGAIN.
ARCHER:
MY HELMSMAN USED TO RUN FREIGHT.
THE TWO OF YOU
WOULD PROBABLY HAVE
A LOT TO TALK ABOUT.
SKALAAR: NO, THE "TEZRA"
ISN'T LIKE ANY OTHER CARGO SHIP.
SHE WAS THE FIRST OF HER CLASS,
THE FASTEST EVER BUILT.
NOW, SHE COULD HAUL
A MILLION METRIC TONS
AT WARP 4.5.
EVEN YOUR STARSHIP
ISN'T CAPABLE OF THAT.
I RETROFITTED
HER ENGINES MYSELF.
ARCHER: YOU NEVER TOLD ME
WHY IT WAS IMPOUNDED.
SKALAAR:
MY BROTHER AND I WERE HAULING
A SHIPMENT OF FIRE SALT.
I THOUGHT I COULD TRIM
2 OR 3 DAYS OFF OUR JOURNEY
BY CUTTING ACROSS
THE MOST INSIGNIFICANT CORNER
OF KLINGON SPACE.
I LEARNED VERY QUICKLY
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS AN INSIGNIFICANT CORNER
OF KLINGON SPACE.
WE WERE LUCKY TO ESCAPE
WITH OUR LIVES,
THOUGH WE DID PAY A PRICE.
ARCHER: THEY TOOK YOUR SHIP.
SKALAAR: AND ITS CARGO, TOO.
MY BROTHER NEVER FORGAVE ME.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO FIND A WAY
TO GET THE "TEZRA" BACK
EVER SINCE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
ARCHER: DID YOU REALLY THINK
I WANTED THIS ENGINE FIXED?
YOU'RE TAKING ME TO BE EXECUTED.
SKALAAR: DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL MEET GOROTH ON TIME.
PHLOX: FEELING ANY BETTER?
T'POL: I'M HUNGRY.
PHLOX: OUR MEALS
WILL BE HERE SOON.
T'POL: I WASN'T REFERRING
TO FOOD.
PHLOX:
I'M WORKING AS QUICKLY AS I CAN.
THIS SERUM SHOULD HELP ALLEVIATE
MOST OF YOUR SYMPTOMS.
T'POL:
THERE'S A FAR SIMPLER TREATMENT.
PHLOX: I'D PREFER TO EXPLORE
A MORE CONVENTIONAL APPROACH.
T'POL: YOU HAVE THE CURE.
IT'S UNETHICAL FOR YOU
TO WITHHOLD IT, DOCTOR.
PHLOX: THIS MATING
CYCLE OF YOURS WAS
ARTIFICIALLY INDUCED.
WE CAN'T BE CERTAIN THAT A--
PHYSICAL ENCOUNTER WOULD HELP.
T'POL: I'M WILLING TO TRY.
PHLOX: SUB-COMMANDER.
T'POL: DON'T BE FRIGHTENED.
I WON'T HURT YOU.
PHLOX: YOU'RE DISTURBING
MY SERUM!
OBVIOUSLY YOU NEED
TO BE SEDATED AGAIN.
T'POL: NO MORE HYPOSPRAYS!
[BEEPS]
PHLOX: ONE OF US
SHOULD PROBABLY ANSWER THAT.
I--IT COULD BE NEWS
ABOUT THE CAPTAIN.
[BEEPS]
THIS IS PHLOX.
TUCKER: Anyone hungry in there?
I brought you some supper.
PHLOX: JUST IN THE NICK OF TIME,
COMMANDER.
IT WOULD BE BEST
IF YOU REMAINED HERE.
TUCKER: HOW ARE YOU
TWO HOLDING UP?
PHLOX: WELL ENOUGH.
HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE
TO LOCATE CAPTAIN ARCHER?
TUCKER: WE'RE TRACKING ANOTHER
WARP SIGNATURE.
HOPEFULLY THIS ONE'S
THE REAL THING.
ARE THOSE THE ONES YOU WANTED?
PHLOX: YES. THANK YOU.
T'POL: IS THAT FOOD?
TUCKER: YEAH.
I HAD CHEF MAKE YOU SOME...
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?
PHLOX:
SHE'S DEVELOPED A SLIGHT FEVER.
NOTHING TO BE CONCERNED ABOUT.
[BEEPS]
REED:
Bridge to Commander Tucker.
TUCKER: GO AHEAD.
REED: We're approaching
the coordinates.
TUCKER: ON MY WAY.
CALL IF YOU NEED ANYTHING.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
REED: TWO MATCHING
WARP SIGNATURES,
BOTH IN THE UPPER ATMOSPHERE.
MORE SUBSPACE BEACONS.
THERE IS A SHIP ON THE SURFACE.
IT SEEMS TO HAVE SUFFERED
ENGINE DAMAGE.
BUT IT'S NOT TELLARITE.
TUCKER: BIO-SIGNS?
REED: ONE.
TUCKER: OPEN A CHANNEL.
KAGO-DARR: YES?
TUCKER: SORRY TO BOTHER YOU,
BUT WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A TELLARITE SHUTTLE.
HAVE YOU SEEN ONE?
KAGO-DARR: HOW MUCH DID
THE KLINGONS OFFER YOU?
TUCKER: KLINGONS?
TUCKER: LOOK, THERE MUST BE
SOME SORT OF
MISUNDERSTANDING HERE.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR OUR CAPTAIN.
KAGO-DARR: YOUR CAPTAIN,
HE'S GOT A PRICE ON HIS HEAD.
HE'S PROBABLY HALFWAY
TO KLINGON SPACE BY NOW.
TUCKER: TRAVIS, HOW CLOSE ARE WE
TO KLINGON SPACE?
TRAVIS:
LESS THAN SIX LIGHT-YEARS.
TUCKER: IF THAT TELLARITE'S
LOOKING TO COLLECT
SOME KIND OF REWARD,
WE'D BETTER FIND HIM
BEFORE HE GETS THERE.
SET A COURSE.
TAKE US BACK TO WARP.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
GAAVRIN:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
SKALAAR: I NEED YOUR HELP.
GAAVRIN:
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE BROUGHT HIM!
SKALAAR: YOU THINK
I WOULD'VE COME HERE
IF I HAD A CHOICE?
I NEED AN ANTIMATTER INJECTOR.
GAAVRIN: AND I SUPPOSE YOU HAVE
NO WAY OF PAYING FOR IT.
SKALAAR:
DO YOU KNOW WHO THIS IS?
HE'S THE ONLY PRISONER
WHO'S EVER ESCAPED
FROM RURA PENTHE.
THE KLINGONS ARE OFFERING
A FORTUNE TO GET HIM BACK.
TELL HIM.
TELL HIM!
GAAVRIN:
IF I GIVE YOU THE INJECTOR,
YOU HAVE TO PROMISE
NEVER TO COME BACK HERE.
SKALAAR:
OF COURSE I'M COMING BACK.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE
MY FIRST OFFICER.
GAAVRIN: THAT WAS YEARS AGO!
I WORK HERE NOW.
SKALAAR:
SCRUBBING PLASMA INJECTORS?
IS THAT HOW YOU WANT
YOUR CHILDREN TO SEE YOU?
GAAVRIN: IT'S BETTER
THAN HUNTING CRIMINALS.
SKALAAR: YOU THINK THAT
I ENJOY SPENDING MY TIME
WITH VERMIN LIKE HIM?
GAAVRIN: I HAVE WORK TO DO.
SKALAAR: PLEASE DON'T TURN
YOUR BACK ON ME AGAIN.
WE CAN RECLAIM THE "TEZRA."
GAAVRIN: YOU WON'T WANT
THAT SHIP AFTER YOU SEE IT.
SKALAAR: WHY NOT?
GAAVRIN:
THE KLINGONS CANNIBALIZED HER.
EVERY POWER RELAY,
EVERY CONDUIT.
SKALAAR: THE ENGINES?
GAAVRIN: THEY'RE GONE.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE INJECTOR.
BUT AFTER THAT,
I WANT YOU TO LEAVE.
ARCHER:
WHAT DO YOU PLAN TO DO NOW?
SKALAAR: GET THAT INJECTOR
AND INSTALL IT.
ARCHER: AND THEN?
I SUPPOSE YOU'LL TURN ME OVER
TO THE KLINGONS.
I'LL BE...
DISEMBOWELED WITH
ONE OF THOSE
NASTY-LOOKING SWORDS OF THEIRS.
AND YOU'LL COLLECT
YOUR 9,000 DARSEKS.
BUT IT WON'T GET YOU
THE "TEZRA" BACK.
SKALAAR: WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO SAY?
ARCHER: THE KLINGONS TOOK
YOUR FREIGHTER, YOUR LIVELIHOOD.
DAMAGED YOUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH YOUR BROTHER.
AND WHAT DO YOU GET IN EXCHANGE?
9,000 DARSEKS.
DOESN'T SEEM LIKE
A VERY FAIR TRADE TO ME.
SKALAAR: WHAT CHOICE DO I HAVE?
I TOLD YOU, IF I LET YOU GO,
THEY'D KILL ME.
ARCHER: MAYBE NOT.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN ABOARD
GOROTH'S SHIP?
SKALAAR: TWICE. WHY?
[T'POL SPEAKS VULCAN]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[REPEATS IN VULCAN]
PHLOX: I BEG YOUR PARDON?
T'POL: LET ME OUT.
PHLOX: YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THAT.
T'POL: THE HEAT!
IT'S UNBEARABLE!
PHLOX:
IF I LOWER THE TEMPERATURE,
THE SERUM WILL START TO CONGEAL.
T'POL: I DON'T WANT
YOUR SERUM! OPEN THE DOOR!
PHLOX: I ASSURE YOU YOU'RE
GOING TO FEEL MUCH BETTER
IN JUST A FEW MINUTES.
T'POL: OPEN IT!
PHLOX:
THIS WILL ONLY TAKE A MOMENT.
YOUR BIOCHEMICAL IMBALANCE
IS GROWING WORSE.
IF WE DON'T TREAT IT NOW,
THE DAMAGE TO YOUR LIMBIC SYSTEM
COULD BE IRREVERSIBLE.
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF, T'POL.
IT COULD KILL YOU!
T'POL: STAY AWAY FROM ME.
PHLOX: ONE INJECTION.
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
[T'POL GRUNTS]
[PHLOX SIGHS]
PHLOX: VERY WELL.
YOU'RE FREE TO GO.
42864.
THAT'S THE LOCKING CODE.
DENOBULAN MEDICAL ETHICS
PREVENT ME
FROM TREATING PATIENTS
AGAINST THEIR WILL.
42864!
[BUZZES]
[T'POL GROANS]
PHLOX: PHLOX TO THE BRIDGE.
TUCKER: Tucker here.
PHLOX: YOU MAY WANT
TO EVACUATE "D" DECK.
REED: SHE'S STILL
IN THIS SECTION.
THE DOCTOR SAYS SHE'S
IRRATIONAL, SO USE CAUTION.
CREWMAN: YES, SIR.
T'POL: MALCOLM!
[T'POL BREATHING HEAVILY]
I NEED YOUR ASSISTANCE.
REED: WE'VE BEEN VERY WORRIED
ABOUT YOU, SUB-COMMANDER.
LET'S GET YOU BACK
TO THE DOCTOR.
T'POL:
I CAN'T RETURN TO THE DOCTOR.
HE'S REFUSING TO TREAT ME.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN?
REED: I BEG YOUR PARDON?
T'POL: SINCE YOU'VE MATED?
I'VE SEEN THE WAY
YOU LOOK AT ME.
ON THE BRIDGE.
REED: WHY DON'T WE DISCUSS
THIS IN DECON?
T'POL: MY QUARTERS
WOULD BE MORE COMFORTABLE.
REED:
DR. PHLOX WAS VERY INSISTENT.
FOLLOW ME, SUB-COMMANDER.
[T'POL SHOUTS IN VULCAN]
SKALAAR: WELCOME!
[BEEPING]
GOROTH: THE EMPIRE NEVER FORGETS
ITS ENEMIES.
[GOROTH SHOUTS IN KLINGON]
SKALAAR: WHAT ABOUT MY PAYMENT?
6,000 DARSEKS.
SKALAAR: WE AGREED TO NINE.
GOROTH: DID WE?
ARCHER: THAT'S BLOOD MONEY,
SKALAAR. HOPE YOU ENJOY IT.
[BEEPS]
HOSHI: WE'RE BEING
HAILED, COMMANDER.
HOSHI: IT'S THE TELLARITE SHIP.
TUCKER: WHAT?
PUT HIM THROUGH.
[CLICK]
[CLICKING]
[BEEPING]
[ALARM]
REED: I'VE GOT THEM.
BEARING 226 MARK 71.
TUCKER: SET A COURSE.
GO TO TACTICAL ALERT.
[DOOR OPENS]
[BUZZES]
GOROTH: WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'LL GO, HUMAN?!
THERE ISN'T A PLANET
WITHIN 50 LIGHT-YEARS.
HE WON'T GET FAR.
DROP OUT OF WARP.
OFFICER:
SHOULD I CHARGE WEAPONS?
GOROTH: NO. I WANT HIM ALIVE.
TRAVIS: I SEE HIM.
800,000 KILOMETERS.
TUCKER: WHAT ABOUT THE KLINGONS?
REED: THEY'RE CLOSING IN ON HIM.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
TUCKER: RETURN FIRE!
DEPLOY THE GRAPPLER!
TRAVIS: THEY'RE NOT
MAKING IT EASY.
TUCKER: MALCOLM?
REED:
I'M DOING THE BEST I CAN, SIR.
THEIR WEAPON PORTS
ARE HEAVILY SHIELDED.
TRAVIS: GOT IT.
TUCKER: BRING HIM IN!
REED: THEIR WEAPONS ARE DOWN.
TUCKER: THE POD?
TRAVIS: SAFE AND SOUND.
LAUNCH BAY 2.
TUCKER:
LET'S GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DEVICE SNAPS]
PHLOX: YOU'LL BE PLEASED
TO KNOW THE MICROBE'S
BEEN ELIMINATED
FROM YOUR SYSTEM.
YOUR PREMATURE MATING CYCLE
HAS ENDED.
T'POL: DID I DO ANYTHING
INAPPROPRIATE?
[PHLOX CHUCKLES]
PHLOX: I'VE HAD PATIENTS
TREAT ME FAR WORSE.
T'POL: DID WE?
PHLOX: OH, DENOBULAN MALES
AREN'T COMFORTABLE
DISCUSSING SUCH TOPICS.
T'POL: I'D APPRECIATE IT IF YOU
DIDN'T MENTION THIS TO ANYONE.
PHLOX: I'D NEVER VIOLATE
A PATIENT'S PRIVACY.
TUCKER: ROUGH RIDE?
ARCHER: HUH. WHAT'S
THE STATUS OF THE KLINGONS?
TUCKER:
WE DAMAGED THEIR PORT NACELLE.
THEY'RE LIMPING BACK TO KRONOS.
ARCHER: WHERE'S T'POL?
TUCKER: UH, SHE'S IN DECON
WITH DR. PHLOX.
ARCHER: WHAT HAPPENED?
REED: IT'S A LONG STORY.
[BEEPS]
HOSHI:
YOU'RE BEING HAILED, CAPTAIN.
SKALAAR:
I SEE YOU MADE IT BACK SAFELY.
ARCHER: DO YOU THINK
THE KLINGONS KNOW
YOU GAVE ME THAT LOCK PICK?
SKALAAR:
I DON'T SEE WHY THEY WOULD.
ARCHER: WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH YOUR REWARD?
SKALAAR: I'M NOT SURE.
IF YOU KNOW OF
AN OLD FREIGHTER FOR SALE...
ARCHER: I'LL KEEP MY EYES OPEN.
SKALAAR:
BE CAREFUL, CAPTAIN.
IT'S LIKELY THE KLINGONS
WILL DOUBLE THEIR BOUNTY.
ARCHER: I HOPE YOU WON'T
BE THE ONE TO COLLECT IT.
SKALAAR: NO PROMISES.