♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT
GONNA CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CHANCELLOR: TWICE!
TWICE HE'S BEEN CAPTURED,
AND TWICE HE'S ESCAPED.
OUR MAGISTRATE SHOULD NEVER
HAVE SHOWN HIM MERCY.
HE SHOULD HAVE BEEN
EXECUTED FOR HIS CRIMES.
COUNCILOR: YOU HAD
A SIMPLE MISSION, DURAS--
LOCATE THE REBELS
THAT ARCHER WAS HARBORING
AND RETURN THEM TO THE EMPIRE.
BUT YOU FAILED.
ARCHER MADE A FOOL OF YOU.
CHANCELLOR:
WE ARE OFFERING YOU A CHANCE
TO REGAIN YOUR COMMAND
AND YOUR HONOR.
DURAS: I WILL NOT FAIL.
[FIST HITS CHEST]
REED: IT HAS TO BE SOMETHING
PRETTY SERIOUS.
TUCKER: WHAT'S GOING ON?
REED:
THE CAPTAIN WANTS TO TALK TO US.
TUCKER: ABOUT WHAT?
HOSHI: HE'S SPEAKING
TO ADMIRAL FORREST.
IT'S THE THIRD TIME
IN THE LAST HOUR.
TUCKER: WELL, SOMETHING'S
OBVIOUSLY UP.
PHLOX: I CAN'T REMEMBER
THE LAST TIME HE ASKED ME
TO JOIN THE SENIOR STAFF
FOR A BRIEFING.
REED: MAYBE IT HAS
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THE FA--
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER:
THERE'S BEEN AN ATTACK ON EARTH.
TUCKER:
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "AN ATTACK"?
ARCHER: A PROBE.
THEY DON'T KNOW
WHERE IT CAME FROM.
IT FIRED A WEAPON
THAT CUT A SWATH
4,000 KILOMETERS LONG...
FROM FLORIDA TO VENEZUELA.
THERE MAY HAVE BEEN
A MILLION CASUALTIES.
REED: A MILLION?
ARCHER: WE'VE BEEN RECALLED.
TUCKER: DID THEY SAY WHY?
ARCHER: I DIDN'T ASK.
TRAVIS: IT'LL TAKE AWHILE
TO GET BACK, SIR.
[INTERCOM BEEPS]
MAN: Bridge to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: GO AHEAD.
MAN: IT'S ADMIRAL FORREST, SIR.
ARCHER: UNDERSTOOD.
SET A COURSE, TRAVIS.
WARP 5.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
TUCKER: EXCUSE ME, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: TRIP.
TUCKER: WHEN YOU SPOKE
TO ADMIRAL FORREST...
DID HE SAY
WHAT PART OF FLORIDA WAS HIT?
ARCHER: NO, I'M SORRY.
TUCKER:
AH, SHE MAY HAVE BEEN AWAY.
ARCHITECTS TAKE A LOT OF TRIPS.
ARCHER: OLDER OR YOUNGER?
TUCKER: MY BABY SISTER.
WHEN WE WERE IN SCHOOL, I...
MADE SURE ALL THE BOYS
IN HER CLASS
GOT A GOOD LOOK AT ME.
NONE OF THEM
EVER MESSED WITH HER.
ARCHER: MAYBE SHE WAS AWAY.
[TUCKER CLEARS THROAT]
TUCKER: ANYTHING YOU CAN TELL
ME ABOUT WHAT THE ADMIRAL SAID?
ARCHER: THE NUMBER
OF CASUALTIES HAS BEEN REVISED.
IT'S UP TO THREE MILLION.
TUCKER:
WHY WOULD SOMEONE DO THIS?
[DOOR CHIMES]
ARCHER: COME IN.
T'POL:
I SPOKE WITH AMBASSADOR SOVAL.
ARCHER: AND?
T'POL: A VULCAN TRANSPORT
LOCATED THE POD IN CENTRAL ASIA.
THEY RETRIEVED IT AND BROUGHT
IT TO STARFLEET HEADQUARTERS.
ARCHER: WHAT DO THEY KNOW?
T'POL: VERY LITTLE.
THERE WAS
A PILOT KILLED ON IMPACT.
TUCKER: WHO THE HELL WAS HE?
WHAT SPECIES?
T'POL: THEY DON'T KNOW.
TUCKER: DID THEY SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT WHAT
PART OF FLORIDA WAS HIT?
T'POL: NO.
ARCHER:
TRIP'S SISTER LIVES IN FLORIDA.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
ARCHER: ARCHER.
REED: Captain,
we've got Suliban ships,
eight of them,
approaching at high warp.
ARCHER: JUST WHAT WE NEED.
TACTICAL ALERT.
HAIL THEM.
[BEEPING]
HOSHI: THEY'RE NOT RESPONDING.
ARCHER: TRY AGAIN.
REED: THE CAPTAIN!
[DOOR OPENS]
SILIK: THERE'S SOMEONE
WHO NEEDS TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
ARCHER: SILIK!
I KNEW YOU'D HAVE
SOMETHING TO WITH THIS.
SILIK: DO WITH WHAT?
ARCHER: MILLIONS OF PEOPLE.
YOU KILLED MILLIONS OF PEOPLE!
SILIK: I'M AFRAID I DON'T
KNOW WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THAT WOULDN'T BE WISE, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER:
WHAT THE HELL AM I DOING HERE?
SILIK: THERE'S SOMEONE
WHO NEEDS TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
HE HAS INFORMATION
YOU SHOULD FIND HELPFUL.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU WON'T BE HARMED.
ARCHER: INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT?
SILIK: SOMETHING
TO DO WITH YOUR SPECIES.
IT'S IN GREAT DANGER.
HE CAN SEE YOU MORE
CLEARLY IF YOU MOVE CLOSER.
ARCHER: WHO IS HE?
SILIK:
HE WANTS TO TALK TO YOU.
IT WOULD BE FOOLISH
TO IGNORE HIM.
ARCHER: WHAT DO YOU WANT?
FUTURE MAN:
YOUR PLANET WAS ATTACKED.
ARCHER: I'M AWARE OF THAT.
FUTURE MAN:
WHAT YOU'RE NOT AWARE OF IS WHY.
THE PROBE WAS SENT BY THE XINDI.
THEY LEARNED THAT THEIR WORLD
WOULD BE DESTROYED BY HUMANS
IN 400 YEARS.
ARCHER: HOW WOULD
THEY KNOW WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
IN 400 YEARS?
FUTURE MAN: THEY WERE TOLD
BY PEOPLE FROM THE FUTURE--
PEOPLE WHO CAN COMMUNICATE
THROUGH TIME.
ARCHER: ARE THEY THE ONES
THE SULIBAN ARE WORKING FOR?
FUTURE MAN:
THE SULIBAN WORK FOR ME.
ARCHER: SO YOU'RE
THE ONE WHO TRIED TO START
A CIVIL WAR
IN THE KLINGON EMPIRE,
THE ONE WHO'S MANIPULATED
MY MISSION FROM DAY ONE.
FUTURE MAN: THE PEOPLE
WHO HAVE CONTACTED THE XINDI
BELONG TO ANOTHER FACTION.
THE PROBE WAS ONLY A TEST.
THE XINDI ARE BUILDING
A FAR MORE POWERFUL WEAPON.
WHEN IT IS COMPLETED,
THEY WILL USE IT
TO DESTROY EARTH.
ARCHER: ANNIHILATE US
BEFORE WE CAN ANNIHILATE THEM.
WHY ARE YOU TELLING ME THIS?
FUTURE MAN: THE XINDI
WERE NOT SUPPOSED TO LEARN
ABOUT THEIR FUTURE.
IF THEY DEPLOY THIS WEAPON,
IT WILL CONTAMINATE
THE TIMELINE.
YOU MUST NOT LET THAT HAPPEN.
ARCHER:
WHY SHOULD I BELIEVE YOU?
FUTURE MAN: YOU HAVE
NO CHOICE BUT TO BELIEVE ME.
T'POL: IF THIS TIME TRAVELER
IS TRYING TO PROTECT HUMANITY,
WHY DIDN'T
HE TELL YOU ALL OF THIS
BEFORE MILLIONS OF
PEOPLE WERE KILLED?
ARCHER: HE DIDN'T THINK
WE'D BELIEVE HIM.
HE'S PROBABLY RIGHT.
T'POL: I'M SURE STARFLEET
AND THE HIGH COMMAND
WILL FIND A FAR MORE
LOGICAL EXPLANATION
OF WHO ATTACKED EARTH.
ARCHER:
HE MAY BE TELLING THE TRUTH.
IF HE IS, I NEED YOUR SUPPORT,
NOT YOUR DAMN SKEPTICISM!
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
APRIL 24, 2153.
THE JOURNEY HOME
HAS BEEN VERY DIFFICULT.
WE'VE NOW LEARNED THAT
OVER 7 MILLION PEOPLE WERE LOST.
TRAVIS: CAPTAIN...
THAT'S OUR SUN.
[BEEPING]
REED:
A VESSEL'S DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
ARCHER: WHERE?
TRAVIS: 200 KILOMETERS OFF PORT.
ARCHER: WHO ARE THEY?
REED:
THEY'VE FIRED SOME KIND OF...
REED: THAT ONE TOOK
OUT BOTH FORWARD PHASE CANNONS.
ARCHER:
YOU STILL HAVE TORPEDOES.
T'POL:
IT'S A KLINGON BIRD-OF-PREY.
[BEEPS]
THEY WANT YOU, SIR.
THEY'RE SAYING
THEY WON'T DESTROY "ENTERPRISE"
IF YOU SURRENDER TO THEM.
"ARCHER'S AN ENEMY
OF THE EMPIRE.
HE MUST BE BROUGHT TO JUSTICE
IF HONOR'S TO BE REGAINED."
ARCHER: DURAS.
OFFICER: BOTH THEIR
NACELLES ARE CRIPPLED.
DURAS: WEAPONS?
HELMSMAN:
THEIR CANNONS ARE DOWN.
DURAS: CEASE FIRING.
PREPARE A BOARDING PARTY.
OFFICER:
THREE SHIPS APPROACHING.
EARTH VESSELS.
DURAS: RETURN FIRE!
HELMSMAN: SHIELDS ARE FAILING!
DURAS: ARE THEY OFF-LINE?
HELMSMAN: NO, SIR!
DURAS: THEN KEEP FIRING!
HELMSMAN: WE'VE LOST
DISRUPTOR BANKS THREE AND FOUR.
DURAS: AAH!
WITHDRAW!
GO TO WARP SPEED.
HOSHI:
IT'S CAPTAIN RAMIREZ, SIR,
ON THE "INTREPID."
RAMIREZ: WHAT THE HELL
WAS THAT ALL ABOUT?
ARCHER:
A KLINGON NAMED DURAS.
HE'S NOT VERY FOND OF ME.
RAMIREZ:
WELCOME HOME, CAPTAIN.
I WISH IT WAS UNDER
BETTER CIRCUMSTANCES.
I TOLD COMMAND
EVERY WORD YOU SAID.
FORREST: THEY'RE HAVING
A HARD TIME BUYING IT.
ARCHER: DO THEY HAVE A BETTER
IDEA OF WHO DID THIS?
AND HOW ABOUT THE VULCANS?
I SUPPOSE YOU THINK
I'M HALLUCINATING.
SOVAL: OUR SCIENCE
DIRECTORATE HAS DETERMINED
THAT TIME TRAVEL IS IMPOSSIBLE.
ARCHER: ARE YOU WILLING TO RISK
A SECOND ATTACK?
ALL I'M ASKING
IS TO TAKE "ENTERPRISE"
AND FIND THESE XINDI.
WHAT DO WE HAVE TO LOSE?
A SINGLE STARSHIP?
SEEMS LIKE A SMALL PRICE TO PAY
IF THERE'S ONE CHANCE
IN A MILLION THAT HE'S RIGHT.
SOVAL: DO YOU KNOW WHERE THESE
COORDINATES HE GAVE YOU ARE?
ARCHER: AT WARP 5,
ABOUT A THREE-MONTH TRIP.
SOVAL: THEY'RE INSIDE
THE DELPHIC EXPANSE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S THAT?
SOVAL: A REGION OF SPACE
NEARLY 2,000 LIGHT-YEARS ACROSS.
VULCAN SHIPS HAVE ENTERED IT,
BUT ONLY A FEW HAVE RETURNED.
ARCHER:
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE BERMUDA TRIANGLE.
SOVAL: THERE HAVE BEEN REPORTS
OF FIERCE AND DANGEROUS SPECIES,
UNEXPLAINED ANOMALIES.
IN SOME REGIONS, EVEN THE LAWS
OF PHYSICS DON'T APPLY.
20 YEARS AGO, A KLINGON VESSEL
EMERGED FROM THE EXPANSE.
EVERY CREWMAN ON BOARD
HAD BEEN ANATOMICALLY INVERTED,
THEIR BODIES SPLAYED OPEN.
AND THEY WERE STILL ALIVE.
YOU'D BE MORE THAN FOOLISH
TO PURSUE THIS COURSE OF ACTION.
ARCHER:
IT'S A RISK I'M WILLING TO TAKE.
AND I IMAGINE MOST OF MY CREW
WOULD BE WITH ME.
SOVAL: THIS IS TYPICAL
OF YOUR IMPULSIVENESS.
YOU'D BE PUTTING
YOUR CREW'S LIVES AT STAKE
WHEN YOU HAVE NO EVIDENCE THAT
ANYTHING YOU WERE TOLD IS TRUE.
FORREST: WE'VE LOST
A LOT OF PEOPLE ALREADY, JON.
STARFLEET COMMAND WOULD NEED
SOME KIND OF PROOF
BEFORE THEY'D LET YOU GO.
ARCHER: I'M NOT SURE THE PERSON
I SPOKE TO
WAS FROM THE FUTURE OR NOT.
BUT HE KNEW THIS WOULD BE
THE REACTION THAT I'D GET.
SO...
HE DID GIVE ME PROOF.
[BEEPING]
FORREST: JON?
ARCHER: THIS
IS QUANTUM-DATING THE DEBRIS.
TAKE A LOOK.
THE PRINCIPAL ALLOY
IN THIS PIECE
WAS SYNTHESIZED
WITHIN THE LAST FOUR YEARS.
THIS ONE, ABOUT A YEAR EARLIER.
SOVAL: WHAT EXACTLY ARE
YOU TRYING TO SHOW US, CAPTAIN?
ARCHER: 12 YEARS FOR THIS PIECE.
FORREST: YOUR POINT, JONATHAN?
ARCHER: I'M GETTING TO IT.
YOU MIGHT FIND THIS INTERESTING.
FORREST: YOUR SCANNER'S
NOT WORKING PROPERLY.
ARCHER: WHY IS THAT, SIR?
FORREST: THE QUANTUM DATE
READS -420.
ARCHER:
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THAT?
FORREST:
QUANTUM DATING ALWAYS REGISTERS
IN POSITIVE NUMBERS.
ARCHER: THEN I GUESS
THIS ONE'S NOT WORKING, EITHER.
SOVAL: YOU SAID HE TOLD YOU
THIS FACTION FROM THE FUTURE
COULD ONLY COMMUNICATE
THROUGH TIME.
SO HOW DO YOU SUGGEST
THEY GOT THIS COMPONENT
TO THE XINDI?
ARCHER:
I HAVEN'T THE SLIGHTEST IDEA.
BUT THAT DOESN'T CHANGE
WHAT'S ON THESE SCANNERS.
THIS FRAGMENT'S FROM THE FUTURE
UNLESS YOU
HAVE ANOTHER EXPLANATION.
SOVAL:
A LACK OF ANOTHER EXPLANATION
DOESN'T MAKE
YOUR ASSUMPTION CORRECT.
FORREST:
I'LL SPEAK WITH COMMAND.
ARCHER: I'D LIKE TO TAKE A LOOK
IN THERE.
SOVAL: ARE YOU
SUGGESTING THIS IS A XINDI?
ARCHER: I SURE AS HELL
WOULD LIKE TO FIND OUT.
PHLOX: THIS IS DR. FER'AT.
ARCHER: I DON'T HAVE A LOT
OF TIME. WHAT'S UP?
PHLOX: THE VULCAN RESEARCH
TEAM DETECTED TRACES
OF PYRITIC RADIATION
IN THE ALIEN DEBRIS.
ARCHER:
WHY DIDN'T STARFLEET CATCH IT?
FER'AT: SOME OF OUR TECHNOLOGY
IS STILL MORE ADVANCED
THAN YOURS.
PHLOX: WE'RE GOING TO NEED
TO TREAT ANYONE
WHO GOT CLOSE TO THE WRECKAGE.
DR. FER'AT IS HERE TO DETERMINE
THE EXTENT OF YOUR EXPOSURE.
FER'AT:
IT SHOULDN'T TAKE LONG.
PLEASE HAVE A SEAT.
HAVE YOU EXPERIENCED
ANY NAUSEA OR DIZZINESS?
ARCHER: NO.
FER'AT:
NUMBNESS IN YOUR EXTREMITIES?
ARCHER: I FEEL FINE.
FER'AT:
I WAS TOLD THAT YOU THINK
A PIECE OF THE WRECKAGE
CAME FROM THE FUTURE.
ARCHER: I KNOW.
VULCANS DON'T BELIEVE
IN TIME TRAVEL.
FER'AT: SOME OF US DO.
TELL ME,
THIS TIME TRAVELER YOU MET,
WAS HE HUMANOID?
ARCHER:
HOW DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
FER'AT: I WAS BRIEFED
BEFORE COMING HERE.
ARCHER: HE SEEMED HUMANOID,
BUT I COULDN'T SEE HIM
THAT WELL.
FER'AT: HAVE YOU ENCOUNTERED
PEOPLE FROM THE FUTURE BEFORE?
ARCHER: A NUMBER OF TIMES.
DOES THIS HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE RADIATION?
FER'AT: I WAS JUST CURIOUS.
IT MUST BE VERY DIFFICULT
TO HAVE SO MANY PEOPLE
QUESTION YOUR STORY.
DOES IT UPSET YOU?
ARCHER: DOESN'T HELP.
FER'AT:
BUT HOW DOES IT MAKE YOU FEEL?
ARCHER:
I TOLD YOU, IT DOESN'T HELP.
FER'AT: I CAN SENSE SOME
ANGER WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT THIS.
ARCHER: IT'S KIND OF STRANGE
THAT A VULCAN
WOULD BE SO INTERESTED
IN MY FEELINGS.
FER'AT: JUST CURIOUS.
YOUR EXPOSURE SEEMS MINIMAL.
YOU'LL REQUIRE
VERY LITTLE TREATMENT.
I IMAGINE YOU MUST HAVE FELT
VERY ANXIOUS
AFTER MEETING SOMEONE
FROM THE FUTURE.
ARCHER: WHY WOULD YOU
IMAGINE THAT?
PHLOX: I'M AFRAID THIS
EXAMINATION IS OVER.
FER'AT: I'M NEARLY FINISHED.
PHLOX: YOU ARE FINISHED.
I JUST CHECKED
THE VULCAN DATABASE.
THERE'S ONLY
ONE DR. FER'AT LISTED.
AND HE'S NOT A PATHOLOGIST.
HE'S A PSYCHIATRIC ANALYST.
ARCHER:
SOVAL SURE IS PERSISTENT.
WHAT DID HE WANT YOU TO DO,
COME BACK WITH PROOF
THAT I'M OUT OF MY MIND?
PHLOX: YOU COME TO MY
SICK BAY UNDER FALSE PRETENSES?
WHERE ARE YOUR MEDICAL ETHICS?!
FER'AT: I'M JUST
DOING WHAT I WAS TOLD TO.
ARCHER: WELL, I'M TELLING
YOU TO GET THE HELL OFF MY SHIP.
IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND, PHLOX,
I'D LIKE YOU TO ESCORT OUR GUEST
TO THE AIRLOCK.
PHLOX: GLADLY.
REED: I'M SO SORRY.
TUCKER:
THE HOUSE WAS OVER THERE.
LESS THAN A KILOMETER.
SEE OVER THERE?
THAT WAS THE OLD MOVIE THEATER.
WHEN WE WERE KIDS,
IF I DIDN'T TAKE MY SISTER
WITH ME,
SHE'D SCREAM LIKE A BANSHEE.
[TUCKER SIGHS]
REED: ARE YOU CERTAIN
SHE WAS HERE WHEN THIS HAPPENED?
TUCKER: SOMEONE WOULD HAVE
HEARD FROM HER IF SHE WASN'T.
ARCHER:
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
AFTER DAYS OF DEBATE,
STARFLEET'S FINALLY INFORMED ME
THAT WE'RE TO PROCEED
WITH OUR NEW MISSION.
THE NX-02.
FORREST: SHE'LL BE
READY TO LAUNCH IN 14 MONTHS.
ARCHER: A LONG TIME.
FORREST: HOPEFULLY YOU'LL
BE BACK WELL BEFORE THEN.
ARCHER: HOPEFULLY.
WHAT KIND OF ARMAMENTS
WILL SHE HAVE?
FORREST: SAME COMPLEMENT OF
WEAPONS THAT YOU'LL HAVE
ONCE THE RETROFIT IS DONE.
HAVE YOU TOLD YOUR CREW?
ARCHER: THIS MORNING.
FORREST:
HOW MANY ARE STAYING ABOARD?
ARCHER: SOME HAVEN'T
DECIDED YET,
BUT I DON'T THINK MORE THAN
8 OR 9 WILL BE LEAVING.
I TALKED TO GENERAL CASEY
A FEW HOURS AGO.
FORREST: HIS TEAM SHOULD
BE ARRIVING AT 1800 HOURS.
I WAS SURPRISED
YOU ASKED FOR THEM.
YOU THINK YOU'LL BE COMFORTABLE
WITH MILITARY ON BOARD?
ARCHER: I DON'T HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH NON-STARFLEET PERSONNEL.
THE GENERAL TELLS
ME THESE ARE THE BEST HE HAS.
I'M GONNA NEED
ALL THE MUSCLE I CAN GET
WHEN WE CROSS INTO THE EXPANSE.
FORREST: YOU WEREN'T TOLD
WHERE IN THIS EXPANSE
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO LOOK?
ARCHER: NOT EVEN A HINT.
FORREST:
THIS WEAPON THEY'RE BUILDING--
DID HE SAY HOW LONG
IT WAS GOING TO TAKE THEM?
ARCHER: I DON'T THINK
HE WOULD HAVE WARNED US
IF WE DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE
OF STOPPING THEM.
PHLOX: SUB-COMMANDER.
IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
T'POL: ARE YOU CONFIDENT
WITH YOUR DECISION, DOCTOR?
PHLOX:
WHAT DECISION WOULD THAT BE?
T'POL: TO REMAIN
ON "ENTERPRISE."
CREWMAN FULLER JUST
TOLD ME A SHUTTLE'S ON ITS WAY
WITH 200 SNOW BEETLES.
PHLOX: THEY COULD BE
FOR MY REPLACEMENT.
T'POL: THERE ISN'T
A DOCTOR IN STARFLEET
THAT WOULD HAVE THE SLIGHTEST
IDEA OF WHAT TO DO WITH THEM.
PHLOX: AND, UH, WHAT ABOUT YOU?
T'POL: THE HIGH COMMAND
HAS MADE IT CLEAR
THAT THEY DON'T WANT ME
TO ENTER THE DELPHIC EXPANSE.
PHLOX: I'M MORE INTERESTED
IN HEARING WHAT YOU WANT.
T'POL: IT'S NOT MY PLACE
TO DISOBEY THE HIGH COMMAND.
PHLOX: NONSENSE.
YOU'VE DONE IT BEFORE.
IT'S INTERESTING,
YOU AND I--
THE ONLY ALIENS
ON BOARD THIS VESSEL.
TO GO OR TO STAY?
FOR ME, IT WAS A SIMPLE
QUESTION OF LOYALTY
TOWARD THE CAPTAIN
AND THE SAD REALIZATION
THAT HE'LL NEED ME MORE
THAN EVER
ON SUCH A CRUCIAL MISSION.
BUT FOR YOU,
IT'S A MORE DIFFICULT DECISION.
DOES YOUR ALLEGIANCE LIE
WITH THE HIGH COMMAND
OR WITH CAPTAIN ARCHER?
WOMAN:
THIS JUST ARRIVED, DOCTOR.
PHLOX: AH.
T'POL: THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
[BEETLES CHIRPING]
REED: PHOTONIC TORPEDOES.
THEIR RANGE
IS OVER 50 TIMES GREATER
THAN OUR CONVENTIONAL TORPEDOES,
AND THEY HAVE A VARIABLE YIELD.
THEY CAN KNOCK THE COMM ARRAY
OFF A SHUTTLEPOD
WITHOUT SCRATCHING THE HULL,
OR THEY CAN PUT
A THREE-KILOMETER CRATER
INTO AN ASTEROID.
TUCKER: HOW LONG IS IT GONNA
TAKE TO RECONFIGURE THE TUBES?
REED: WELL, WE'VE GOT
THREE TEAMS WORKING ON IT.
THEY PROMISE ME IT'LL BE
DONE BEFORE WE LEAVE SPACEDOCK.
BUT I'VE GOT TO START
INTEGRATING THEM
INTO THE POWER GRID.
TUCKER: LET'S GO.
REED: IS THERE GOING TO BE
SOME KIND OF SERVICE?
TUCKER: FOR LIZZIE?
REED: MM-HMM.
TUCKER: IF YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT A FUNERAL,
IT'S KIND OF POINTLESS
WHEN THERE'S NOTHING LEFT.
REED: I GUESS
I WAS TALKING ABOUT A MEMORIAL.
TUCKER: MY SISTER WASN'T BIG
ON MEMORIALS.
REED: I READ THERE WAS
A DAY OF REMEMBRANCE
FOR ALL THE VICTIMS
A COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO.
I'M SORRY YOU MISSED IT.
TUCKER: WHY ARE YOU
SO OBSESSED WITH MEMORIALS?
REED: I'M NOT OBSESSED.
TUCKER: SHE'S DEAD.
SO ARE SEVEN MILLION OTHERS.
SHE WAS NO MORE IMPORTANT
THAN ANY OF THEM.
REED:
SHE WAS MORE IMPORTANT TO YOU.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH ADMITTING THAT.
TUCKER: I'M GETTING REAL TIRED
OF YOU TELLING ME
WHAT I CAN AND CAN'T DO.
AND WHILE WE'RE AT IT,
I DON'T NEED YOU TO REMIND ME
THAT ELIZABETH WAS KILLED.
SO JUST LET IT ALONE.
MAYBE YOU
SHOULD PAY MORE ATTENTION
TO UPGRADING YOUR WEAPONS.
SO YOU CAN BLOW THE HELL
OUT OF THESE BASTARDS
WHEN WE FIND THEM.
ARCHER:
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, ADMIRAL,
WHAT IS THE POINT
OF ME WATCHING THIS?
IS IT SUPPOSED TO FRIGHTEN ME,
MAKE ME CHANGE MY MIND
ABOUT COMMANDING THIS MISSION?
SOVAL: IT'S IMPORTANT FOR YOU
TO SEE WHAT YOU'LL BE FACING.
THE "VAANKARA" WAS
IN THE DELPHIC EXPANSE
FOR LESS THAN TWO DAYS
WHEN WE RECEIVED
A DISTRESS CALL.
THIS TRANSMISSION
ARRIVED SIX HOURS LATER.
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING
AND SCREAMING ]
LESS THAN AN HOUR LATER,
THE "VAANKARA" WAS DESTROYED.
THERE WAS NO INDICATION
OF A MALFUNCTION OR AN ATTACK.
ARCHER: ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THE CREW WAS RESPONSIBLE?
SOVAL: I'M SUGGESTING
YOU RECONSIDER THIS MISSION.
ARCHER:
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE, SIR?
SOVAL:
I NEED TO SPEAK WITH YOU, T'POL.
IF ALL GOES WELL,
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE
TO RETURN TO YOUR DUTIES
ON EARTH WITHIN A YEAR.
THAT IS, IF YOU'RE
STILL INTERESTED.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN BACK TO VULCAN
FOR SOME TIME.
YOU MAY FIND YOUR ASSIGNMENT
AT THE MINISTRY OF INFORMATION
REFRESHING.
T'POL: I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY I CAN'T STAY
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
SOVAL: YOU'VE SPENT
FAR TOO MUCH TIME WITH HUMANS.
IT WILL BE BEST
IF YOU RETURN HOME FOR AWHILE.
T'POL: YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS CRUCIAL
TO PLACE A VULCAN
ON "ENTERPRISE"
DURING ITS FIRST MISSION.
WHY NOT NOW?
SOVAL: YOU WERE THERE TO PROVIDE
LOGIC TO A CREW OF HUMANS
WHO INSISTED ON LEAVING
BEFORE THEY WERE READY.
BUT LOGIC CAN'T HELP THEM
INSIDE THE DELPHIC EXPANSE.
T'POL: CAN YOU BE CERTAIN
OF THAT?
SOVAL: THE HIGH COMMAND
WAS QUITE SPECIFIC.
YOU'RE TO RETURN TO VULCAN.
T'POL: I BELIEVE THAT SHOULD
BE MY DECISION.
SOVAL:
THIS IS NOT A MATTER OF CHOICE.
DEFYING THE HIGH COMMAND
WOULD MEAN IMMEDIATE DISMISSAL.
YOU KNOW THAT.
ARCHER: SOVAL AGREED TO
LET US TAKE HER BACK TO VULCAN,
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT WITH YOU.
FORREST: IT'S NOT THAT FAR
OUT OF YOUR WAY.
HOW'S THAT LAST
REFIT TEAM DOING?
ARCHER:
SCHEDULED TO BE DONE BY 0600.
FORREST: I COULD TELL YOU
THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
COUNTING ON YOU.
BUT I DON'T NEED
TO DO THAT, DO I?
ARCHER: NO, SIR.
FORREST: GOOD LUCK, JON.
DURAS: HAVE THEY GONE TO WARP?
OFFICER: NOT YET.
DURAS: CHARGE WEAPONS
AND PREPARE
TO BRING THEM ONLINE.
ARCHER:
IT'S BAD ENOUGH ONE OF US
IS UP IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE NIGHT.
TUCKER:
HOW'S PORTHOS HOLDING UP?
IF NO PEOPLE HAVE RETURNED
FROM THE DELPHIC EXPANSE,
I DOUBT ANY DOGS HAVE.
ARCHER: HE MUST BE
DOING BETTER THAN WE ARE.
HE'S FAST ASLEEP.
TUCKER: HAVE YOU PICKED
A NEW SCIENCE OFFICER?
ARCHER: NO.
TUCKER: YOU'RE GONNA MISS HER,
AREN'T YOU?
ARCHER:
WHEN THEY FIRST ASSIGNED HER,
I FELT LIKE STRANGLING SOVAL.
TUCKER: AH, SHE DOES KIND OF
GROW ON YOU.
ARCHER: I WOULD THINK
YOU'D BE THE FIRST ONE
TO SHOW HER TO THE AIRLOCK.
TUCKER: NAH.
[TUCKER SIGHS]
TO HENRY ARCHER.
I WONDER WHAT
HE WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
IF HE KNEW HIS ENGINE WAS
GONNA HELP SAVE THE HUMAN RACE.
ARCHER: WHEN I GOT THIS JOB,
COMMANDING THE FIRST WARP 5 SHIP
WAS ABOUT
AS BIG A RESPONSIBILITY
AS I COULD HAVE IMAGINED.
THEN WE BEGAN
RUNNING INTO SO MANY...
BAD GUYS,
AND I HAD TO START THINKING MORE
ABOUT THE SAFETY OF 83 PEOPLE.
TUCKER: AND NOW THE STAKES
HAVE GOTTEN A LOT BIGGER.
ARCHER:
WEIGHT OF THE WORLD, TRIP.
TUCKER: LITERALLY.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO GET IN THERE, CAPTAIN,
FIND THE PEOPLE WHO DID THIS.
AND TELL ME WE WON'T
BE TIPTOEING AROUND.
NONE OF THAT
"NONINTERFERENCE" CRAP
T'POL'S ALWAYS
SHOVING DOWN OUR THROATS.
MAYBE IT'S A GOOD THING
SHE'S LEAVING.
ARCHER:
WE'LL DO WHAT WE HAVE TO, TRIP.
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
[EXPLOSION]
T'POL: IT'S DURAS.
ARCHER: YOU'VE BEEN WANTING
TO TEST THOSE NEW TORPEDOES.
REED: WHAT YIELD?
ARCHER: START LOW.
WE JUST WANT TO GET
THEM OFF OUR BACKS.
DURAS: WHAT WAS THAT?!
HELMSMAN: ANTIMATTER WARHEADS!
DURAS: INCREASE SHIELDING
AND TARGET THEIR WEAPON PORTS!
REED:
THEY'RE STILL ON OUR BACKS, SIR.
ARCHER: BRING THE YIELD UP. 50%.
DURAS: I TOLD YOU TO
TARGET THE WEAPON PORTS!
HELMSMAN: THEIR HULL PLATING'S
BEEN ENHANCED!
OFFICER:
OUR WARP DRIVE IS FAILING.
[DURAS GROWLS]
TRAVIS:
THEY'RE DROPPING TO IMPULSE.
REED:
STAND DOWN WEAPONS, SIR?
ARCHER: HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
THEM TO REPAIR THEIR ENGINES?
T'POL: IMPOSSIBLE TO DETERMINE.
ARCHER:
GIVE ME AN EDUCATED GUESS.
T'POL: THREE HOURS.
POSSIBLY MORE.
ARCHER: WHAT'S OUR SPEED?
TRAVIS: WARP 3, SIR.
ARCHER: GO TO 4.5.
IF WE CAN MAKE IT
TO VULCAN SPACE
BEFORE THEY GET
THEIR ENGINES BACK,
THEY'LL THINK TWICE ABOUT
GIVING US ANY MORE TROUBLE.
[DOOR CHIMES]
COME IN.
T'POL: ENSIGN MAYWEATHER
SAYS WE'RE TWO DAYS FROM VULCAN.
ARCHER:
WHY DON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
JUST THINK,
IN TWO DAYS YOU'LL BE
EATING REAL VULCAN FOOD.
T'POL:
CHEF'S DONE AN ADEQUATE JOB
OF APPROXIMATING
VULCAN CUISINE.
ARCHER: WELL, YOU NEVER DID
CARE FOR THE WAY WE SMELL.
AT LEAST YOU WON'T HAVE
TO PUT UP WITH THAT ANYMORE.
T'POL: I'VE GOTTEN USED TO IT.
ARCHER:
HOW ABOUT ALL THOSE EMOTIONS
WE BOMBARD YOU WITH EVERY DAY?
T'POL: I'VE GROWN
ACCUSTOMED TO THAT AS WELL...
SOMEWHAT.
ARCHER:
YOU'RE NOT MAKING THIS EASY.
THERE'S GOT TO BE SOMETHING
YOU'RE LOOKING FORWARD TO
BACK HOME.
T'POL: I DON'T WISH
TO RETURN TO VULCAN.
ARCHER: WHAT?
T'POL: I WANT TO REMAIN
ABOARD "ENTERPRISE"
IF YOU'LL ALLOW ME TO.
ARCHER: IT'S NOT A QUESTION
OF MY ALLOWING YOU.
[SIGHS]
THE HIGH COMMAND
WOULD NEVER AGREE TO IT.
T'POL: I'VE DECIDED
TO RESIGN MY COMMISSION.
ARCHER: WHY?
YOU'VE WORKED SO HARD, T'POL.
T'POL:
YOU'RE TAKING "ENTERPRISE"
INTO A VERY DANGEROUS PLACE.
THIS IS NO TIME FOR ME TO LEAVE.
ARCHER: WE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
T'POL:
YOU NEED A SCIENCE OFFICER,
WHETHER SHE'S A MEMBER
OF THE HIGH COMMAND OR NOT.
ARCHER: I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT WHO TO PROMOTE.
T'POL: YOU NEED ME, CAPTAIN.
[DOOR OPENS]
ARCHER: KEEPING AWAY
FROM THOSE KLINGONS
ISN'T GOING TO BE
AS EASY AS WE THOUGHT.
TRAVIS: SIR?
ARCHER: WE'RE NOT
GOING TO VULCAN.
MR. MAYWEATHER...
SET A COURSE
FOR THE DELPHIC EXPANSE.
TRAVIS: AYE, SIR.
ARCHER:
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE BEEN TRAVELING
AT WARP 5 FOR SEVEN WEEKS.
THE CREW IS ANXIOUS
TO BEGIN OUR MISSION.
DISTANCE?
TRAVIS:
NEARLY A MILLION KILOMETERS.
TUCKER: LOOKS A HELL OF
A LOT CLOSER THAN THAT.
T'POL: A COMMON MISTAKE
WHEN VIEWING
SOMETHING OF THIS SIZE.
ARCHER: MAGNIFY.
TUCKER: NOT VERY HELPFUL.
TRAVIS: IT'S NOT THAT DENSE
ALL THE WAY THROUGH, IS IT?
ARCHER: THE VULCANS SAID
THE EXPANSE IS SURROUNDED
BY THICK LAYERS
OF THERMOBARIC CLOUDS.
WHEN THEIR LAST SHIP WENT IN,
IT TOOK THEM ALMOST SIX HOURS
TO GET THROUGH IT.
ANYTHING ON LONG-RANGE SENSORS?
T'POL:
NOTHING BEYOND THE PERIMETER.
ARCHER: 0.2 IMPULSE, TRAVIS.
LET'S HEAD IN.
ANYTHING?
T'POL: NOTHING YET.
HOSHI: WE'VE BEEN IN HERE
FOR MORE THAN SIX HOURS.
ARCHER: LET'S BE PATIENT.
TUCKER: WE LAUNCHED
THE COMMUNICATIONS BUOY, SIR.
WE GOT A TEST SIGNAL
THROUGH TO STARFLEET.
ARCHER: KEEP THEM APPRISED
OF OUR POSITION.
HOSHI: AYE, SIR.
[BEEPING]
ARCHER: GOT SOMETHING?
T'POL: YES.
TUCKER: PROBABLY THE BUOY.
T'POL: NOT UNLESS YOU LAUNCHED
THREE OF THEM.
HELMSMAN: THE TARGETING
SCANNERS WON'T LOCK ON.
DURAS: THEN GET CLOSER.
TUCKER:
I THOUGHT YOU SAID THE KLINGONS
WOULDN'T GO INTO THE EXPANSE.
ARCHER:
WE'RE NOT IN THE EXPANSE YET.
HOLD YOUR COURSE.
GO TO FULL IMPULSE.
TUCKER: I WOULDN'T
RECOMMEND THAT, CAPTAIN.
THE INTAKE MANIFOLDS
ARE HAVING
A TOUGH ENOUGH TIME AS IT IS.
ARCHER: YOU HEARD ME, TRAVIS.
TRAVIS:
THEY'RE KEEPING UP WITH US, SIR.
HOSHI: WE'RE BEING HAILED.
ARCHER: PUT IT UP.
DURAS:
SURRENDER OR BE DESTROYED.
ARCHER: GO TO HELL!
DURAS:
YOU'RE OUTGUNNED, ARCHER.
COME ABOUT
AND PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
IF YOU DON'T OBEY MY ORDERS,
I'LL --
T'POL: THE PERIMETER CLOUD
IS DISSIPATING.
I'M DETECTING CLEAR SPACE AHEAD.
ARCHER: THAT'S WHY DURAS
WANTS US TO COME ABOUT.
HE'S AFRAID OF THE EXPANSE.
INCREASE SPEED, TRAVIS.
OFFICER: THE OTHER SHIPS
ARE GOING TO TURN BACK.
DURAS: COWARDS.
WE'LL DO IT OURSELVES.
HELMSMAN:
WE'RE TOO CLOSE TO THE EXPANSE.
REED: ONLY ONE LEFT, SIR.
ARCHER: KEEP FIRING.
T'POL: THE EXPANSE
IS LESS THAN FIVE MINUTES AWAY.
TUCKER: MAYBE HE'LL TURN
AROUND LIKE HIS FRIENDS.
ARCHER: I WOULDN'T BET ON IT.
YOUR NEW TORPEDOES
AREN'T HAVING THE SAME EFFECT
AS LAST TIME.
REED: DURAS HAS TRANSFERRED
HIS AFT SHIELDS FORWARD.
OUR WEAPONS
CAN'T PENETRATE THEM.
[CREWMEN GROANING]
TUCKER: WE JUST LOST 3
ANTIMATTER INJECTORS, CAPTAIN.
ANY MORE
AND WE'RE IN BIG TROUBLE.
ARCHER: IF HE'S TRANSFERRED
HIS SHIELDING FORWARD,
WHAT'S PROTECTING HIS STERN?
TUCKER: DOES IT MATTER?
HE'S CHASING US.
ARCHER:
WHAT'S PROTECTING HIS STERN?
T'POL: MINIMAL SHIELDING.
ARCHER: YOU THINK YOU
CAN PULL OFF AN L-4
AT THIS SPEED?
TRAVIS: I CAN TRY, SIR.
ARCHER: THEN LOOK FOR
THE DENSEST CLOUD FORMATION
YOU CAN FIND.
CAPTAIN ARCHER TO ALL HANDS,
HOLD ON.
TRAVIS: CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: LOOKS GOOD TO ME.
DURAS: WHERE ARE THEY?
ARCHER: FIRE.
NICE GOING, TRAVIS.
TRAVIS: I HOPE YOU
DON'T ASK ME TO DO THAT
TOO OFTEN, SIR.
[ARCHER SIGHS]
HOSHI:
THE EXPANSE IS AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER: DID YOU LOSE ANY
MORE OF THOSE INJECTORS?
TUCKER: NO, SIR.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
ARCHER: SURE YOU STILL WANT TO
TAG ALONG?
T'POL: IT'S ONLY LOGICAL.
ARCHER: STRAIGHT AND STEADY,
MR. MAYWEATHER.
LET'S SEE WHAT'S IN THERE.