LAST TIME ON "ENTERPRISE"...
THERE'S BEEN
AN ATTACK ON EARTH.
WE'VE BEEN RECALLED.
THE PROBE WAS SENT BY THE XINDI.
THEY LEARNED THAT THEIR WORLD
WOULD BE DESTROYED BY HUMANS
IN 400 YEARS.
IS THERE GOING TO BE
SOME KIND OF SERVICE?
MY SISTER WASN'T BIG
ON MEMORIALS.
SHE WAS NO MORE IMPORTANT
THAN ANY OF THEM.
SHE WAS MORE IMPORTANT TO YOU.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH ADMITTING THAT.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THIS IS A XINDI?
I'D SURE AS HELL
WOULD LIKE TO FIND OUT.
YOU'RE TO RETURN TO VULCAN.
I BELIEVE THAT SHOULD BE
MY DECISION.
WE RECEIVED A DISTRESS CALL.
EVERY CREWMAN ON BOARD
HAD BEEN ANATOMICALLY INVERTED,
THEIR BODIES SPLAYED OPEN,
AND THEY WERE STILL ALIVE.
I WANT TO REMAIN
ABOARD ENTERPRISE.
I'VE DECIDED TO RESIGN
MY COMMISSION.
YOU THINK YOU'LL BE COMFORTABLE
WITH MILITARY ON BOARD?
I DON'T HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH NON-STARFLEET PERSONNEL.
I'M GONNA NEED
ALL THE MUSCLE I CAN GET
WHEN WE CROSS INTO THE EXPANSE.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO GET IN THERE, CAPTAIN,
FIND THE PEOPLE WHO DID THIS.
AND TELL ME WE WON'T
BE TIPTOEING AROUND.
NONE OF THAT
"NONINTERFERENCE" CRAP
T'POL'S ALWAYS
SHOVING DOWN OUR THROATS.
WE'LL DO WHAT WE HAVE TO, TRIP.
IT COULD SIMPLY BE
A COINCIDENCE.
YOU'RE BEING NAIVE.
THEIR PLANET IS
50 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
IT IS NOT A COINCIDENCE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW YOUR CONTACTS
GAVE YOU ACCURATE INFORMATION?
[ CLICKING ]
THEY HAVE NO WAY OF KNOWING
THAT WE LAUNCHED THE PROBE.
HOW MANY HUMANS ARE ABOARD?
WHEN WILL IT BE READY?
THE NEXT SERIES OF TESTS
IS BEING PREPARED.
WE WILL ACCOMPLISH NOTHING
IF ALL YOU DO IS RUN TESTS.
WE MUST BE PATIENT.
WE MUST FOLLOW THE PLAN
THAT WE ALL AGREED TO.
[ SCREECHING ]
LEARN EVERYTHING YOU CAN
ABOUT THIS HUMAN VESSEL.
[ HISSES ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
HOW LONG TILL WE GET THERE?
ANOTHER THREE HOURS.
DID THE FREIGHTER CAPTAIN SAY
WHO WE'RE SUPPOSED TO CONTACT?
THE FOREMAN OF THE NORTH MINE.
HE'S EXPECTING US.
WHAT MAKES THIS CAPTAIN
SO CERTAIN
ONE OF THE MINERS IS XINDI?
HE'S NOT.
HE JUST SAID HE THINKS THERE WAS
A XINDI ABOARD A TRANSPORT
HE TOOK THERE A FEW YEARS AGO.
AND IT IS SAFE TO ENTER ORBIT?
THERE ARE
NO SECURITY CONSIDERATIONS?
HE DIDN'T MENTION ANY.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
WE SHOULD APPROACH WITH CAUTION.
THE FREIGHTER CAPTAIN
WAS OF QUESTIONABLE CHARACTER.
-WHERE ARE WE, MALCOLM?
-SIR?
THIS ROOM.
WHAT DID IT USED TO BE?
A STORAGE BAY, SIR.
CONDUIT HOUSINGS, I BELIEVE.
BUT IT GOT RETROFITTED.
STARFLEET WENT TO
A LOT OF TROUBLE
TO TURN IT INTO
OUR NEW COMMAND CENTER.
WHY IS THAT, MALCOLM?
BECAUSE OF OUR MISSION, SIR.
-TO FIND THE XINDI, RIGHT?
-RIGHT.
SO THIS
STATE-OF-THE-ART EQUIPMENT WAS
PUT IN HERE TO HELP US GATHER
ALL THE PIECES OF THE PUZZLE,
FIGURE OUT
WHO'S TRYING TO DESTROY EARTH.
RIGHT.
SIX WEEKS.
WE'VE BEEN IN THIS EXPANSE
FOR SIX WEEKS.
WHAT DATA HAVE WE GATHERED?
WHAT PIECES OF THE PUZZLE HAVE
WE STARTED TO PUT TOGETHER?
NOT A SINGLE ONE.
WE DON'T HAVE THE LUXURY OF
BEING SAFE OR CAUTIOUS ANYMORE.
AND IF THE ONLY LEAD WE CAN FIND
COMES FROM A FREIGHTER CAPTAIN
OF QUESTIONABLE CHARACTER,
THEN THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
UNDERSTOOD?
UNDERSTOOD.
[ LAUGHS ]
IS THIS SEAT TAKEN?
MA'AM.
I'M HOSHI SATO.
WE'VE FAMILIARIZED OURSELVES
WITH ALL THE BRIDGE OFFICERS,
ENSIGN.
I'M MAJOR HAYES.
THIS IS SERGEANT KEMPER.
CORPORALS ROMERO AND CHANG.
MILITARY ASSAULT COMMAND.
CAPTAIN ARCHER
WANTED THE BEST.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE ALL GOTTEN
YOUR SPACE LEGS.
SOME OF US ARE STILL VISITING
DR. PHLOX EVERY MORNING.
WONDERS OF MODERN MEDICINE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF OUR DOCTOR, SERGEANT?
I IMAGINE YOU DON'T
RUN INTO MANY DENOBULANS
IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA.
ACTUALLY, I'M STATIONED
OUTSIDE OF ATLANTA.
NO DENOBULANS, BUT WE HAVE OUR
FAIR SHARE OF ALIEN VISITORS.
YOU MUST HAVE GONE PRETTY DEEP
INTO OUR RECORDS.
I HAVEN'T LIVED IN DULUTH
SINCE JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU MAY HAVE LEFT DULUTH,
BUT YOU'VE STILL GOT PLENTY OF
DULUTH LEFT IN YOUR INFLECTIONS.
-[ LAUGHTER ]
-EXCUSE ME?
ENSIGN SATO'S A LINGUIST,
KEMPER.
YOU GIVE HER ENOUGH TIME,
SHE COULD PROBABLY TELL YOU
WHAT STREET YOU GREW UP ON.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHERE WE'RE HEADED, ENSIGN?
I'M SURE CAPTAIN ARCHER WILL LET
US KNOW WHEN HE HAS REASON TO.
LET'S HOPE IT'S SOON.
THE QUICKER YOU FOLKS
FIND THESE XINDI,
THE QUICKER WE CAN GET TO WORK.
WE HAVE A BRIEFING
IN A FEW MINUTES.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE US.
-JUST BAY 2?
-YES, SIR.
CARGO BAYS 1 AND 3
SEEM UNAFFECTED.
-WHEN DID IT START?
-ABOUT 10 MINUTES AGO.
ENSIGN McFARLANE
GOT PRETTY BANGED UP,
BUT HE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
YOU SURE IT'S NOT A PROBLEM
WITH THE GRAV-PLATING?
TRUST ME, CAPTAIN.
IT'S NOT THE GRAV-PLATING.
CAREFUL, SIR.
STAY CLOSE TO THE DOOR.
JUST GIVE IT A MINUTE.
[ RUMBLING ]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S NOT THE GRAV-PLATING.
ANY VOLATILE MATERIAL
IN THOSE CONTAINERS?
I WOULD'VE KNOWN BY NOW.
SEAL IT OFF.
LET'S HOPE THIS LITTLE ANOMALY
DOESN'T LAST ANY LONGER
THAN THE OTHERS DID.
[ RUMBLING ]
AH. UH...
COME LOOK AT THIS.
THE PIGMENTATION
IS FAR MORE COLORFUL
THAN I WOULD HAVE SUSPECTED.
WHAT ARE WE LOOKING AT?
OH, UM, XINDI EPITHELIAL CELLS
HARVESTED FROM THE CORPSE
THEY FOUND
INSIDE THE CRASHED PROBE.
-IT LOOKS MORE LIKE SCALES.
-PRECISELY.
WHEN I'M FINISHED CONSTRUCTING
MY PHYSIOMETRIC PROFILE,
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED TO FIND
HE HAS, UH,
REPTILIAN CHARACTERISTICS.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME?
DO YOU HAVE ANY SIBLINGS?
NO.
COMMANDER TUCKER HAD ONE SISTER.
SHE WAS KILLED IN THE ATTACK.
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
HE'S HAVING DIFFICULTY
DEALING WITH THE LOSS.
IT'S TO BE EXPECTED.
MORE SPECIFICALLY,
IT'S AFFECTING HIS SLEEP.
I'VE BEEN GIVING HIM SEDATIVES,
BUT I'D LIKE TO SEE HIM
START TAPERING OFF.
I'M NOT SURE I UNDERSTAND.
I BELIEVE THE COMMANDER
WOULD BE A FINE CANDIDATE
FOR VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE.
I DOUBT THE COMMANDER
WOULD HAVE THE PATIENCE
TO SIT IN ONE PLACE LONG ENOUGH
TO GET THROUGH
THE FIRST POSTURE.
I'M CERTAIN,
WITH YOUR DELICATE GUIDANCE --
"DELICATE" IS NOT A WORD
I ASSOCIATE WITH MR. TUCKER.
THE INSTRUCTION
OF NEUROPRESSURE IS...
A VERY INTIMATE ACT.
AND HE'S SUFFERED
A VERY INTIMATE LOSS.
HE NEEDS YOUR HELP.
HAVE HIM COME TO MY QUARTERS.
THERE'S, UM, ONE LITTLE PROBLEM.
ASSUMING THAT YOU'D AGREE
TO MY REQUEST,
I SUGGESTED ALL OF THIS TO
COMMANDER TUCKER EARLIER TODAY.
HE WAS LESS THAN ENTHUSIASTIC.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
PERHAPS IF I COULD GET HIM
TO GO TO YOUR QUARTERS,
YOU MIGHT BE ABLE
TO CONVINCE HIM
OF THE LASTING BENEFITS
OF VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE.
WE SHOULD HAVE WORN
E.V. SUITS.
THE DOCTOR SAID IT WAS SAFE
FOR SHORT PERIODS.
HUH! SAFE?
YOU CALL THIS SAFE?
I'VE BEEN IN...
[ COUGHING ]
-TRY NOT TO BREATHE.
-YES, SIR.
[ RATTLING ]
I'M CAPTAIN ARCHER
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
-WE'VE COME TO SEE --
-THIS WAY.
ARCHER.
I'M JONATHAN ARCHER.
THIS IS LIEUTENANT REED.
I'VE BEEN TOLD YOU MIGHT BE ABLE
TO MAKE IT WORTH MY WHILE
IF I WERE TO ARRANGE
A CERTAIN INTRODUCTION.
DEPENDS WHAT YOU MEAN
BY WORTH YOUR WHILE.
WELL, I'VE ALWAYS HAD A FONDNESS
FOR PLATINUM,
SPECIFICALLY
IN ITS LIQUEFIED STATE.
I'M AFRAID WE DON'T CARRY
PRECIOUS METALS ON BOARD.
MM.
PITY.
I'M SURE THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
WE COULD OFFER YOU.
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
I DON'T MAKE A HABIT OF ALLOWING
PEOPLE TO INTERRUPT MY WORKERS,
XINDI OR OTHERWISE!
WHAT ABOUT
THE ANTIMATTER RELAYS?
THEIR LININGS ARE COATED
WITH A PLATINUM-COBALT ALLOY.
TRIP COULD PROBABLY STRIP THEM
DOWN AND SEPARATE THE METALS.
HOW MUCH PLATINUM
ARE WE TALKING ABOUT?
WELL, I'M A REASONABLE MAN.
I'M SURE YOU COULD PART WITH,
SAY, HALF A LITER.
I'D NEED TO SEE THIS MAN,
SCAN HIM,
CONFIRM THAT HE'S XINDI.
[ COUGHING ]
THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY.
WHY WOULD YOU DO THIS?
UNFORTUNATE ACCIDENT.
I EXPECT TO
SEE YOU BACK TOMORROW.
GOOD DAY.
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
ELIZABETH!
LIZZIE, YOU'VE GOT TO
GET OUT OF THERE!
ELIZABETH!
PLEASE!
GET OUT OF THERE!
[ NO AUDIO ]
[ GASPS ]
A BLOOD SAMPLE
WOULD HAVE SUFFICED.
SOME SALIVA.
IS IT XINDI?
YES. AND NO.
I NEED SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE CONCRETE, DOCTOR.
THE GENETIC PROFILE
IS NEARLY IDENTICAL
TO THE TISSUE SAMPLES TAKEN
FROM THE CORPSE FOUND ON EARTH.
THEIR BASE PAIR SEQUENCING
IS FAR CLOSER THAN SAY, UM,
HUMANS AND CHIMPANZEES.
NEARLY IDENTICAL, BUT NOT QUITE.
LIKE HUMANS AND NEANDERTHALS?
A REASONABLE ANALOGY.
AFTER ANALYZING THE REMAINS
OF THE XINDI CORPSE,
I WAS ABLE TO PROVIDE
THE COMPUTER WITH ENOUGH DATA
TO CREATE THIS RENDERING.
HOWEVER, THIS HUMANOID
IS REPTILIAN.
THAT FINGER IS NOT.
IT'S COVERED WITH SKIN,
NOT UNLIKE YOURS OR MINE.
BUT IT'S XINDI, ALL THE SAME.
I WISH I COULD BE
MORE HELPFUL, CAPTAIN.
-SIR.
-HOW'S IT COMING?
WE'RE GONNA END UP STRIPPING
MORE THAN 200 RELAYS
TO GET HALF A LITER
OF LIQUEFIED PLATINUM.
BUT YOU'LL HAVE IT
BY THIS AFTERNOON.
LET ME KNOW WHEN IT'S READY.
YOU OKAY?
I'M FINE.
I'VE GOT TO HAVE
SOMETHING STRONGER
TO HELP ME SLEEP TONIGHT, DOC.
VERY WELL.
COME BY AT AROUND 2200 HOURS.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
THANKS.
YOU'RE AWARE THIS STUFF
IS VOLATILE
ABOVE 30 DEGREES CELSIUS?
I'M FAMILIAR WITH THE PROPERTIES
OF LIQUID PLATINUM.
I'VE INSULATED
THE OUTER CONTAINER.
IT SHOULD KEEP EVERYTHING
PRETTY STABLE.
THERE'S A LITTLE MORE
THAN A HALF LITER IN HERE.
WHAT EXACTLY DO YOU WANT
WITH OUR XINDI FRIEND?
HE'S NOT VERY ATTRACTIVE,
ESPECIALLY AFTER
HIS RECENT SURGERY.
I HAVE SOMETHING
TO DISCUSS WITH HIM.
AND WHAT MIGHT THAT BE?
I BROUGHT YOU
WHAT YOU ASKED FOR.
NOW LET ME SEE THE XINDI.
[ BEEPING ]
HIS WORK GROUP SHOULD BE AWAKE
IN ABOUT AN HOUR'S TIME.
IT TOOK SIX OF MY MEN
HALF THE NIGHT
TO EXTRACT THIS PLATINUM.
I THINK YOU COULD WAKE HIM
AN HOUR EARLY.
[ GROANS ]
[ COUGHING ]
IS TRELLIUM-D
THE ONLY THING YOU MINE HERE?
THE ONLY THING.
TRELLIUM-D.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR WITH IT.
WHAT'S IT USED FOR?
INSULATION.
MOSTLY FOR INTERSTELLAR VESSELS.
WHAT INSULATION
DOES YOUR SHIP USE, CAPTAIN?
OUR OUTER HULL IS LINED
WITH DURANIUM.
I IMAGINE YOU MUST HAVE
A VERY LARGE CREW.
AND WHY WOULD YOU IMAGINE THAT?
[ GRUNTING ]
TAKE YOUR TIME.
DO I HAVE YOU
TO THANK FOR THIS?
THE FOREMAN SAID
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
-DID HE?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
-YOU'RE XINDI?
NINE-FINGERED XINDI.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHERE'S YOUR HOMEWORLD?
YOU CAME ALL THE WAY
TO THIS HIDEOUS PLANET,
BRIBED THE FOREMAN TO SEE ME,
FOR WHAT?
DIRECTIONS TO MY PLANET?
I FIND THAT HARD TO BELIEVE.
WE HAVE IMPORTANT BUSINESS
WITH YOUR PEOPLE.
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
WHERE TO FIND THEM?
WELL, IF YOU WANT INFORMATION,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO HELP ME
ESCAPE FROM THIS PLACE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, ESCAPE?
DO THESE LOOK LIKE VOLUNTEERS?
WE'RE CAPTIVES, SLAVES!
A SIMPLE SET OF COORDINATES.
THAT'S ALL I WANT.
I'M PREPARED TO PAY YOU.
THE ONLY PAYMENT I'M INTERESTED
IN IS MY FREEDOM.
IF YOU CAN'T PROVIDE ME
WITH THAT, STOP WASTING MY TIME!
[ GRUNTING ]
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING
IN THIS PLACE,
AND I DON'T PARTICULARLY CARE.
BUT WE DIDN'T COME HERE
TO STAGE A PRISON BREAK.
SO WHY DON'T YOU
JUST GIVE US THE COORDINATES,
AND WE'LL ALL STOP WASTING
EACH OTHER'S TIME?!
NOT UNTIL YOU GET ME
OFF THIS PLANET.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT SURE WHY,
BUT I'M JUST ITCHING
TO KICK THE HELL OUT OF YOU.
TRIP.
TAKE IT EASY.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-ARCHER HERE.
-Captain.
THERE ARE THREE WARSHIPS
APPROACHING AT WARP.
THEIR HULL ALLOYS MATCH THE
MINING TOWERS ON THE SURFACE.
HOW LONG BEFORE THEY GET HERE?
TWO HOURS, SIR.
Go to tactical alert.
We're heading back
to the shuttlepod.
UNDERSTOOD.
SHUTTLEPOD?
DO YOU HAVE A STARSHIP IN ORBIT?
YOU'VE MADE IT SO EASY FOR THEM.
USUALLY THEY HAVE TO GO OUT
AND FIND SHIPS
TO REPLENISH THEIR LABOR FORCE.
YOU FLEW
RIGHT INTO THEIR TRAP!
[ LAUGHS ]
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
-[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
-ENTERPRISE, RESPOND.
YOU MIGHT CONSIDER WAITING FOR
YOUR COLLEAGUES TO RESCUE YOU,
BUT IT SOUNDS LIKE THEY'RE
ABOUT TO BECOME QUITE BUSY.
IF YOU HAVE A SHUTTLEPOD ON THE
SURFACE, I CAN GET YOU TO IT.
BUT YOU'LL HAVE TO
TAKE ME WITH YOU.
[ BEEPING ]
THERE'S AN AUDIO MESSAGE
COMING IN FROM THE MINE FOREMAN.
-THIS IS ENTERPRISE.
-I'm afraid your captain
AND HIS ASSOCIATE ARE
GOING TO BE SLIGHTLY DELAYED.
WE HAVE THREE
CARGO VESSELS APPROACHING
AND WE'VE HAD TO BEGIN
deionizing our landing decks.
HOW LONG A DELAY?
NO MORE THAN AN HOUR.
WE'VE DETECTED YOUR CARGO SHIPS.
THEY'RE HEAVILY ARMED.
TRELLIUM-D IS A HIGHLY
valued substance.
And I'm certain you've noticed
that this is not one of
the friendlier regions of space.
CAN I TALK TO CAPTAIN ARCHER?
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
HE REQUESTED TO SPEAK TO A MINER
WHO RESIDES ON LEVEL 22.
I SPOKE WITH HIM
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
The deionizing
process prevents us
from communicating
with the lower levels.
I'LL HAVE HIM CONTACT YOU
AS SOON AS HE RETURNS.
KEEP TRYING TO REACH
THE CAPTAIN.
SOMETHING DOESN'T SMELL RIGHT.
I WANT YOU
TO COME UP WITH A PLAN
TO RECOVER THE CAPTAIN
AND COMMANDER TUCKER.
HAVE IT IN PLACE IN ONE HOUR.
GET MAJOR HAYES TO HELP YOU.
SEWAGE TAKES ON
A WHOLE NEW MEANING
WHEN IT COMES FROM
A DOZEN DIFFERENT SPECIES.
31, TO BE EXACT.
HELP ME WITH THIS.
THERE'S A LEVER
BELOW YOUR KNEES.
PULL IT UP.
PLASMA DUCT 13.
HASN'T BEEN USED
SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE.
WHY IS THERE A HATCH HERE?
THERE'S ONE EVERY EIGHT LEVELS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OPENING THE EMERGENCY BAFFLE.
UP THERE.
IT'S A STEEL PLATE
THAT LOCKS INTO PLACE
DURING MAINTENANCE CYCLES.
FOLLOW ME.
...LOOKS A LITTLE CLOSE
TO THE MINE.
THE IONIZED PARTICLES
WILL COVER OUR DESCENT.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
HAVE YOU HEARD FROM THE CAPTAIN?
NOT YET.
THE FOREMAN ISN'T RESPONDING
TO OUR HAILS.
-THE SHIPS?
-LESS THAN AN HOUR AWAY.
ARE YOU READY?
THEY'RE ARMED TO THE TEETH
DOWN THERE.
BUT IT IS DOABLE.
WE ONLY HAVE
ONE BONE OF CONTENTION.
THE MAJOR HERE
THINKS MY SECURITY TEAM
IS FAR TOO VALUABLE
TO BRING DOWN
AND PUT IN THE LINE OF FIRE.
HE WANTS TO TAKE HIS MEN.
IT'S A SIMPLE MATTER
OF PRIORITIES.
IF THOSE WARSHIPS GET HERE
BEFORE WE RETURN
FROM THE SURFACE,
YOU COULD FIND YOURSELVES
DEALING WITH A BOARDING PARTY.
YOU'D BE IN FAR BETTER HANDS
WITH A SECURITY FORCE
WHO KNOWS ENTERPRISE
INSIDE AND OUT.
I PLAN TO HAVE MY MEN
BACK ON BOARD
WITH THE CAPTAIN AND TRIP
LONG BEFORE THOSE SHIPS ARRIVE.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
WE CAN'T BE CERTAIN OF THAT.
THE DECISION IS YOURS,
LIEUTENANT.
BUT I AGREE WITH MAJOR HAYES.
YOUR TEAM MAY NOT
BE BACK IN TIME.
SELECT SIX OF YOUR MEN
AND MEET ME IN LAUNCH BAY 1.
I'LL BE COMMANDING THE MISSION.
VERY GOOD, SIR.
COMING FROM A MILITARY FAMILY,
I'VE SEEN MEN LIKE HAYES
ALL MY LIFE.
LIEUTENANT?
THAT HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH
WHO KNOWS ENTERPRISE
INSIDE AND OUT.
IT HAD TO DO WITH
WHO THE MAJOR THINKS
IS MORE CAPABLE
OF CARRYING OUT THIS RESCUE.
THEY'RE GONE.
ALL THREE OF THEM.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WE'VE SEARCHED
THE ENTIRE CELL PERIMETER.
POST GUARDS
AT THEIR LANDING CRAFT.
IF THEY GET BACK
TO THEIR STARSHIP,
I'LL LOSE NEARLY
100 NEW WORKERS.
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
IF THIS LEADS TO THE SURFACE...
...WHY DIDN'T YOU USE IT BEFORE?
THE RESIDUE IN THE ATMOSPHERE
IS AT LEAST 30 TIMES MORE TOXIC
THAN IT IS DOWN HERE.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
I'VE HAD THE LUXURY
OF A SHIP WAITING FOR ME.
THE LOWER LEVELS
ARE HYPERSATURATED
WITH IONIZED PARTICLES.
SO YOU'LL HAVE TO
GET WITHIN 100 METERS
TO PICK UP THEIR BIO-SIGNS.
WE'VE GOT LESS THAN
A HALF AN HOUR TO DO IT.
DUCT 13.
THEY'VE OPENED
TWO EMERGENCY BAFFLES.
THEY'RE NEARLY TO THE SURFACE.
WE SHOULD DESTROY
THEIR LANDING POD.
NO.
TOO VALUABLE.
HOW LONG WOULD IT TAKE
TO REDIRECT THE PLASMA FLOW
INTO THAT CONDUIT?
I'LL SEE TO IT.
[ GRUNTS ]
YOU'VE RISKED YOUR LIVES
TO LEARN WHERE MY HOMEWORLD IS
BECAUSE YOU SAY YOU HAVE
IMPORTANT BUSINESS
WITH MY PEOPLE?
WHICH SPECIES?
HAVE YOU EVER EVEN MET A XINDI
BEFORE TODAY?
ONE.
AND HE DIDN'T LOOK
VERY MUCH LIKE YOU.
NOT ALL OF THEM DO.
THERE ARE FIVE DISTINCT SPECIES
OF XINDI
AND FIVE DISTINCT OPINIONS
ON WHICH ONE IS DOMINANT.
[ CLANKING ]
WHAT WAS THAT?
THAT SOUNDED AN AWFUL LOT LIKE
THOSE EMERGENCY BAFFLES
WE OPENED.
WHY WOULD THEY OPEN THE REST?
-IT'LL JUST HELP US GET...
-[ RUMBLING ]
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
THIS DUCT ISN'T USED ANYMORE.
IT ISN'T.
THEY'VE OBVIOUSLY
REROUTED THE PLASMA.
HOW FAR UP
TO THE NEXT MAINTENANCE HATCH?
-HOW FAR?!
-I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK THE SAFEST BET IS TO
HEAD BACK DOWN TO THE LAST ONE.
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S WHERE THE PLASMA
IS COMING FROM.
WE SHOULD GO UP.
SUIT YOURSELF.
IT'S TOO LATE!
WE'LL BE KILLED!
SHUT UP!
JUST SHUT UP!
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO
PICK UP THE PACE, GENTLEMEN.
[ GROANING ]
AAAAH!
WAIT A MINUTE.
GET OUT OF MY WAY.
WHAT THE HELL?
YOU STUPID SON OF A BITCH.
I OUGHT TO OPEN THIS HATCH
AND THROW YOU DOWN INTO...
THEY FORCED ME
TO COME WITH THEM.
THEY SAID THEY'D KILL ME
IF I DIDN'T.
JUST NOW, THIS ONE, HE TRIED TO
THROW ME INTO THE PLASMA.
SAID THEY DIDN'T
NEED ME ANYMORE.
THANK YOU!
IF YOU HADN'T BEEN WAITING HERE,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT --
PICK HIM UP.
I'D HAVE PREFERRED HAVING
YOU JOIN YOUR CREW MEMBERS
AS NEW ADDITIONS
TO MY WORKFORCE.
BUT YOU'VE TURNED OUT TO BE
MORE TROUBLE THAN YOU'RE WORTH.
SELECT A DETAIL.
TAKE THEM TO THE SURFACE.
SHOOT ALL THREE OF THEM.
-YOU OKAY?
-YES, SIR.
NICE SHOT.
[ RUMBLING ]
CAPTAIN!
IT TOOK A LITTLE DOING, SIR, BUT
WE GOT THROUGH THE OUTER HATCH.
WHERE THE HELL DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
YOU PROMISED
TO TAKE ME AWAY FROM HERE.
THAT WAS BEFORE YOUR
LITTLE PERFORMANCE BACK THERE.
NO, PLEASE!
YOU HAVE TO HELP ME!
-YOU HAD YOUR CHANCE.
-THE COORDINATES
OF MY HOMEWORLD.
IF YOU WANT THEM, YOU'LL HAVE TO
TAKE ME WITH YOU.
-YOU'RE LYING.
-NO. I PROMISE YOU.
-REED TO MAYWEATHER.
-Go ahead.
WE'VE GOT THEM.
LOCK ON TO MY LOCATION
AND SET DOWN.
Understood.
GO!
CAPTAIN?
[ BEEPING ]
BOTH SHUTTLEPODS
HAVE LEFT THE SURFACE.
IS EVERYBODY ABOARD?
EVERYBODY PLUS ONE.
-THE WARSHIPS?
-STILL AT WARP 4.
E.T.A --
APPROXIMATELY SEVEN MINUTES.
TELL THE PODS
TO DOCK SIMULTANEOUSLY.
PREPARE TO GO TO MAXIMUM WARP.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE 3 ALIEN WARSHIPS FOLLOWED
ENTERPRISE FOR NEARLY AN HOUR
BUT COULDN'T KEEP UP WITH US.
I GUESS THEY'LL HAVE TO
LOOK ELSEWHERE
FOR NEW ADDITIONS
TO THEIR LABOR FORCE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY, CAPTAIN, BUT
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD DO.
I REALIZE HOW IMPORTANT
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
TO HAVE A XINDI TO HELP US.
HE WASN'T A PARTICULARLY
HELPFUL XINDI, DOCTOR.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
IT WAS EXTREMELY DIFFICULT
AND PAINFUL FOR HIM TO SPEAK,
BUT HE MANAGED TO DICTATE THIS
TO ME BEFORE HE DIED.
HE SAID YOU'D KNOW
WHAT IT MEANT.
I'LL BE DAMNED.
THEY'RE THE COORDINATES.
I MUST HAVE BEEN IN THE SHOWER
FOR TWO HOURS.
AND I STILL HAVE THAT CRAP
IN MY HAIR AND UNDER MY NAILS.
WE CLEARED BIO-SCAN.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
YEAH. THE TWO NEW GUYS
WHO GOT HURT -- ARE THEY OKAY?
THE DOCTOR'S GOT THEM BACK
IN THEIR QUARTERS ALREADY.
YOU GOT TO ADMIT,
THEIR TEAM DID A PRETTY
IMPRESSIVE JOB DOWN THERE.
AH, NOTHING YOUR GUYS
COULDN'T HAVE DONE JUST AS WELL.
I'M NOT SO SURE ABOUT THAT.
SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
ALL RIGHT.
AH.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING, COMMANDER?
TIRED.
YOU SAID YOU'D GIVE ME
SOMETHING TO SLEEP.
VERY WELL.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
[ CLICKS ]
IF, UH, YOU WOULDN'T MIND,
COMMANDER,
I PROMISED T'POL I'D TAKE
THESE BIO-SCANS TO HER QUARTERS,
BUT I STILL HAVE QUITE A BIT
OF WORK TO DO HERE.
NO PROBLEM, DOC.
THANKS.
-SICK BAY TO T'POL.
-Yes, Doctor.
COMMANDER TUCKER IS ON HIS WAY
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
HE BELIEVES I JUST GAVE HIM
A SEDATIVE,
BUT IT WAS ONLY A PLACEBO.
HE'S HAD
A RATHER DIFFICULT DAY.
I BELIEVE YOU HAVE YOUR WORK
CUT OUT FOR YOU.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
SORRY TO DROP BY SO LATE,
BUT, UH, PHLOX SAID
YOU WERE EXPECTING THIS.
THANK YOU.
PLEASE, SIT DOWN.
I DON'T THINK I'D BE
VERY GOOD COMPANY RIGHT NOW.
ANYWAY I STILL HAVE
A FEW MORE SHOWERS TO TAKE
BEFORE I GET ALL THIS
TRELLIUM-D OFF ME.
WOULD YOU LIKE A CUP OF TEA?
THANKS,
BUT IT MIGHT KEEP ME UP.
THE DOCTOR JUST GAVE ME
A SEDATIVE.
YOU'RE HAVING
TROUBLE SLEEPING AS WELL?
I NEVER WOULD HAVE PEGGED YOU
FOR AN INSOMNIAC.
I BELIEVE THE EXPANSE HAS BEEN
DISRUPTING MY REM PATTERNS.
PROBABLY NOTHING
A GOOD HYPOSPRAY COULDN'T CURE.
VULCAN SCIENCE TEACHES US
TO PROMPT OUR BODIES
TO CREATE THEIR OWN MEDICINES.
SO WHY ARE YOU STILL
HAVING TROUBLE SLEEPING?
THE NEURAL NODES THAT NEED
TO BE STIMULATED
ARE DIFFICULT TO REACH.
HMM.
[ SIGHS ]
PERHAPS YOU COULD HELP ME.
WELL, I DON'T REALLY
KNOW IF I CAN...
THREE CENTIMETERS ON EITHER SIDE
OF THE FIFTH VERTEBRA.
WELL...
YOU CAN APPLY
CONSIDERABLE PRESSURE.
I'M NOT SURE
WHICH OF THESE IS, UM...
RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT HERE?
LITTLE CLOSER TOGETHER.
HARDER.
IF I PUSH ANY HARDER,
I'LL KNOCK YOU OVER.
JUST LIKE THAT.
PLEASE CONTINUE.
[ GASPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
THAT WAS FAR MORE EFFECTIVE
THAN A HYPOSPRAY.
GLAD TO BE OF ASSISTANCE.
IT WOULD BE ONLY FAIR
FOR ME TO RETURN THE FAVOR.
PLEASE, DISROBE.
[ Chuckling ] WELL...
I-I'M REALLY FLATTERED,
SUBCOMMANDER.
AND DON'T THINK
UNDER DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES
I-I WOULDN'T JUMP
AT THE CHANCE --
ARE YOU IMPLYING
I'M MAKING SEXUAL ADVANCES?
NO.
NO. NO. NO.
NOT AT ALL.
I-I WAS JUST...
YOU SEE, THE DOCTOR GAVE ME
THIS SEDATIVE, AND I...
...THINK IT'S STARTING TO WORK.
THE DOCTOR INJECTED YOU
WITH A PLACEBO.
HE SENT YOU HERE BECAUSE
HE WANTED ME TO PERSUADE YOU
TO TRY VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE.
AS I PREDICTED,
IT WAS A POINTLESS EXERCISE.
WHY DIDN'T HE JUST ASK ME?
HE DID.
YOU REFUSED.
SO THIS WHOLE THING
WAS JUST A SETUP?
THE DOCTOR KNOWS
HOW INTRANSIGENT YOU CAN BE.
-INTRANSIGENT?
-UNWILLING TO COMPROMISE.
I KNOW WHAT IT MEANS.
BUT IT JUST SO HAPPENS
IT'S NOT TRUE.
I'M AS WILLING TO COMPROMISE
AS ANYONE ELSE.
THEN TAKE OFF YOUR SHIRT.
[ GASPS ]
SIR, WE'RE APPROACHING
THE COORDINATES.
TACTICAL ALERT.
STAND BY WEAPONS.
ANY INDICATIONS
THAT WE'RE BEING SCANNED?
NO, SIR.
NO VESSELS.
NO SIGNS OF TECHNOLOGY.
NOTHING.
HOW MANY INHABITED PLANETS?
I'M NOT DETECTING ANY PLANETS,
INHABITED OR OTHERWISE.
THAT SON OF A BITCH LIED TO US.
PHLOX SAID THE XINDI
USED HIS DYING BREATH
TO GIVE US THESE COORDINATES.
WHY WOULD HE LIE?
SIR, I'M PICKING UP
A DEBRIS FIELD.
A SHIP?
-IT'S A LOT BIGGER THAN THAT.
-PUT IT UP.
IT'S NEARLY
80 MILLION KILOMETERS LONG.
IT WAS A PLANET.
MOVE US IN CLOSER.
HOW LONG AGO DID THIS HAPPEN?
JUDGING BY THE FIELD DISPERSION,
APPROXIMATELY 120 YEARS.
I'M PRETTY SURE THERE WAS
A POPULATION HERE, CAPTAIN.
I'M PICKING UP REFINED METALS
AND TRACES OF ALLOYS.
SOME OF THEM MATCH THE HULL
OF THE XINDI PROBE.
THEY'RE BUILDING A WEAPON,
PLANNING TO ANNIHILATE EARTH
BECAUSE THEY THINK
WE'RE GOING TO DESTROY
THEIR WORLD IN 400 YEARS.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE IF THEIR
WORLD DOESN'T EXIST ANYMORE,
HASN'T EXISTED FOR DECADES?
WE KNOW THE PROBE
THAT ATTACKED EARTH
WAS BUILT SOMEWHERE
IN THIS EXPANSE,
AND IT WAS BUILT RECENTLY.
IT'S LOGICAL
TO ASSUME THE NEW WEAPON
IS BEING DEVELOPED
AT THE SAME LOCATION.
BUT IF IT'S NOT HERE...
PREPARE TO GO TO WARP 4.
WHAT COURSE, SIR?
DEEPER INTO THE EXPANSE.
LONG-RANGE SENSORS ARE SHOWING
INCREASING NUMBERS
OF SPATIAL DISTORTIONS.
YOU HEARD ME, TRAVIS.
THEY SCANNED THE DEBRIS AND LEFT
NEARLY THREE HOURS AGO.
THEIR HEADING?
TOWARD THE ORASSIN
DISTORTION FIELDS.
THEN IT'S UNLIKELY
THEY'LL SURVIVE.
IF THEY ARE
THE FIRST WAVE OF AN INVASION,
IT WOULD BE BEST
FOR US TO REMAIN HIDDEN.
LET THEM KEEP SEARCHING.