( whines )
( barks )
Come here.
What's the problem?
( thud )
Commander.
This can't be right.
Did you run a diagnostic?
Twice.
Let's check those relays.
( chirping )
( indistinct talking )
Oh!
-( beeps )
-Captain to the bridge.
-( beeping )
-We're getting reports of anomalies
from all over the ship.
The warp field's fluctuating.
Bridge to engineering. Report.
I don't get it, Captain.
Half the plasma relays
have reversed polarity.
Shut down the reactor.
I'm trying. But it's not cooperating.
We're losing main power.
Now.
I've restored emergency power,
but most of our primary systems
are still off-line.
Including weapons.
Trip, what's your status?
We've got a hell of a mess
down here, Captain.
It's gonna be a while before
I can even figure out
what just happened.
Keep me posted.
Sir, I'm picking up a vessel.
Eight million kilometers off port.
What's their heading?
Looks like they're holding position.
Or they could be adrift.
Hail them.
Our transceiver's off-line.
What's our best speed?
One-quarter impulse.
Set a course.
Bio-signs?
-( beeping )
-None.
And there's no atmosphere aboard.
Artificial gravity's down as well.
Any sign of what happened to them?
No, sir.
Have you spent much time
in gravity boots, Corporal?
I did a six-week tour on Jupiter station.
The grav-plating went down a few times.
-Only in simulations, sir.
-Same here, Captain.
ARCHER:
This is an alien ship we're boarding.
We could run into magnetic variances.
Watch your step.
-Yes, sir.
ARCHER: We're looking for anything
that could tell us what happened to them.
And don't forget...
Just because sensors didn't pick up
any bio-signs
doesn't mean we won't encounter anyone.
-Set weapons to stun.
-Aye, sir.
( beeping )
Weapons fire.
( grunting )
( gasps )
Captain.
No external injuries.
Let's find the bridge.
Try to access that station.
Download what you can.
We counted 17 bodies.
Most of them died
when their life support ran out.
The others were killed
by particle weapons.
What's our status?
Ensign Sato managed to bring
the transceiver online.
But other than that...
-Archer to Mayweather.
-Go ahead, Captain.
Resume our previous course,
one-quarter impulse.
Understood.
It might be best to complete repairs
before we head deeper into the expanse.
If we encounter any more anomalies...
Those people have been dead
for less than two days.
Whoever attacked them
could still be nearby.
We'll have to make repairs on the move.
Mr. Reed recovered some data
from their bridge.
See what you can make of it.
Let's try it again.
Watch that intermix ratio.
( whirring )
Looking good.
Bring her up to 40%.
Shut it down! Shut it down!
( indistinct talking )
-How's it coming?
-Could be better.
Creating a stable warp field isn't easy
when the laws of physics won't cooperate.
The Cochrane equation...
It's not constant here.
The problem's in the quantum variables.
Every time I try to compensate,
the spatial gradients
get thrown out of whack.
Either we get away from these anomalies,
or we're gonna have to rewrite
the book on warp theory.
And I don't have to tell you how long
it took Zefram Cochrane
the first time around.
What about tactical systems?
Weapons should be up and running
within an hour or two.
Make it a priority.
-You worried about something?
-Weapons, Trip.
As quickly as you can.
Where's Isaac Newton when you need him?
Distance?
3,000 meters and closing.
They're charging weapons.
Can you give me hull plating?
I'm sorry, sir.
Hail them.
( beeping )
2,000 meters.
( yells )
( grunts )
( gun fires )
Hold your fire.
-Are those warheads armed?
-Yeah.
Stun grenade.
Go!
How many more?
Two in cargo bay 1.
Four more in engineering.
Get down there and help Trip.
Corporal.
Woods, you're with me.
( beeping )
They're trying to download our database.
Lock them out.
Increase his inaprovaline
by 50 milligrams.
How are they?
Stable.
However, they've suffered
extensive disruptor burns.
I'd like to start them
on regeneration therapy,
but the imaging chamber
was damaged in the attack.
I'll need a repair team
as soon as possible.
Understood.
Crewman Fuller. I did everything I could.
-What about him?
-A few internal injuries.
I'll need to keep him under observation.
You can observe him in the brig.
-See to it.
-Aye, sir.
You might be interested to know
that I recognize his species.
-He's Osaarian.
-He's not from the expanse?
Not originally.
How bad is it?
They made off
with three photonic torpedoes,
a case of plasma rifles,
two dozen stun grenades.
Chef says they cleaned out
half the food stores.
And cargo bay 2 has been
stripped to the bulkheads.
But that's not the worst of it.
They took every one of our
antimatter storage pods.
All we've got left
is what's in the main reactor.
How long will that last? A month?
Tops.
After that, we're out of gas.
This is all you've got?
The high command hasn't had
much contact with the Osaarians.
They have a large merchant fleet,
but there's no record of piracy.
-Any luck tracking their ship?
-Not yet.
They've found a way
to mask their ion trail.
For people with no history of piracy,
they've gotten pretty good at it.
Keep looking.
It appears they've adapted
their weapons and engines
to compensate for the anomalies.
Pursuing them will be dangerous.
We should consider other alternatives.
Such as what?
Waiting for our antimatter to run dry?
I'm only suggesting that we may be able
to replenish our supplies elsewhere.
Keep looking.
Open it.
( beeps )
Dr. Phlox said your injuries were minor.
Please get up.
Why?
I have a dead crewman.
I didn't kill him.
No. One of your friends did.
But I don't have one of your friends,
I have you.
So get up and look at me.
Thank you.
You're going to help me find your ship.
( chuckles )
And after I've taken back
what they stole from me,
you and your colleagues... are free to go.
If you went anywhere near that ship,
you'd have more than one dead crewman.
I can't help you.
Even if I could,
my captain wouldn't be very interested
in having me back, would he?
Not after I told you where to find him.
That's a risk you'll have to take.
Because the alternative
is going to be a lot less pleasant.
( chuckles ) I don't think
you'd be very comfortable
torturing another man.
You and your crewmates
are far too civilized for that.
Too moral.
I need what was stolen from me.
There's too much at stake to let my...
morality get in the way.
You're obviously new to this expanse.
If you weren't, your ship's hull
would be insulated with trellium-d.
Do you have any idea
what a spatial distortion
can do to a ship
that is not insulated with trellium-d?
What it can do...
to the people inside that ship?
You masked your ion trail. How?
( scoffs )
Well...
My captain's a very clever man.
He has to be.
When you're forced to resort to
desperate measures in order to survive,
you have to be clever.
You need to know how to hide.
So you were forced into piracy.
When we entered this expanse,
we were no different than you.
Two merchant ships
looking for trade routes.
Then the first distortion hit us.
We decided to return home.
But the perimeter,
the thermobaric clouds,
they let you in,
but they don't let you out.
One of our ships was destroyed trying.
After a few more encounters
with the anomalies,`
it wasn't long before we became predators.
This section of the expanse
proved to be ideal for hunting.
When a ship runs aground
due to spatial distortions,
it becomes an easy target.
Our captain told us
we wouldn't harm anyone.
And we didn't.
Not at first.
It takes time to learn to kill
without remorse.
You're not prepared to kill.
Or torture.
( scoffs ) Not yet.
I'm prepared to do whatever
it takes to find your ship.
And if that ends up causing me remorse...
Then it's something
I'm willing to live with.
Think about it.
I've been studying the data
recovered from the derelict.
Apparently they decided to look
for the Osaarians as well.
They found a way to modify their sensors
to detect the ion trail,
but their life support failed
before they had a chance to start.
Did they leave a record
of the modifications?
I've already given it
to Ensign Mayweather.
-What's our tactical situation?
-Hull plating's back online.
We should have phase cannons
within the hour.
Torpedoes?
Lieutenant Reed is still having difficulty
modifying the guidance systems
to compensate for the anomalies.
I'll be in the armory.
( beeping )
Black tea, hot.
You finished rewriting the physics books?
I don't think I'll be taking home
the Nobel Prize any time soon.
A few hours rest
might do you a world of good.
No kidding.
You still can't sleep?
T'Pol's been trying to help,
showing me how to
stimulate my neural nodes.
It's not what you think.
Oh, I wasn't thinking anything.
How are the weapons coming?
The Captain and I managed to bring
the guidance systems online,
but I'm gonna need more time
for the aft launchers.
Fuller knew those torpedo systems
better than anyone.
He won't be easy to replace.
Considering all the hostile aliens
we've met,
I suppose it's fortunate
we haven't lost more people.
I doubt he'll be the last.
There's no reason to get cynical.
Every species we run into
seems to be gunning for us.
We might as well paint
a giant bull's-eye on the hull.
What do you suggest we do?
Turn around and go back to Earth?
All I'm saying is that this mission,
whether it succeeds or not,
is looking like
a one-way ticket all the time.
Captain's starlog, supplemental.
We've been tracking
the Osaarians' ion trail
for the past four hours.
There's still no sign of them.
The trail ends
about 20,000 kilometers ahead.
Any sign of a ship?
Nothing.
T'Pol?
Curious.
The trail resumes after
another 70,000 kilometers.
Let's see it.
Should I alter course?
Not yet.
Why would there be such a large gap?
The ions may have been dispersed
by stellar winds.
There would still be
some residual particles.
Captain.
The particle decay rates don't match.
This one is at least nine hours old.
This one was left less than an hour ago.
Bring weapons online.
Take us to where the first trail ends.
( rumbling )
Travis?
I'm not reading anything.
Power's fluctuating.
Forward plating's down.
Microfractures are forming
on the outer hull.
We should come about.
Keep going.
T'Pol.
It's approximately
19 kilometers in diameter.
Ever seen anything like it?
No.
It's constructed entirely
of a single alloy.
Who could build something that big?
Take us in closer.
That cloaking field is enormous.
Whoever built this thing
went to a great deal of trouble
to conceal it.
Judging from those ion trails,
the Osaarians spent over eight hours here.
I want to find out why.
Any luck scanning the interior?
Our sensors are being deflected.
See if you can find something
that looks like a way in.
Take us into orbit.
I'm detecting what appears to be a portal.
22 degrees north of our current position.
Put it up.
Can you tell what the door's made of?
Polyduranium.
The same metal as the Osaarian's hull.
Can we fit through?
Not with Enterprise.
Then get a pod ready.
( beeping )
I've cycled through
the standard frequencies.
Did you find the locking mechanism?
On the lower right side.
Hold our position.
Try it now.
There's no indication of any ships, sir.
-( beeps )
-Archer to Enterprise.
Go ahead.
-We're heading in.
-Understood.
There's enough energy running through here
to power a dozen cities.
( rumbling )
What's that? Down there.
( beeping )
Those modules
have a breathable atmosphere.
Let's hope there's no one home.
Do you see that docking port, Ensign?
Yes, sir.
( beeps )
We're all clear, sir.
They've been busy.
There are a lot of modules to search.
Fan out. Keep open com links.
They're not going to run out of
stem bolts any time soon.
This way.
Starfleet ration packs.
( communicator beeps )
-Archer.
-I've found something, Captain.
-Travis?
-Over here, sir.
I'm pretty sure it's a cargo manifest.
How's your Osaarian?
Not very good, sir.
Download what you can. Get it to Hoshi.
Tell T'Pol we're gonna need
another search team.
-Aye, sir.
-( rumbling )
Check behind those canisters.
( indistinct talking )
I need help here.
Look at this.
( indistinct talking )
( breathing heavily )
-Commander?
-I had a little accident, doc.
I was reinstalling
the deuterium injectors.
One of them must have had
a little juice left in it.
Second-degree burn.
Hmm. Why don't you have a seat?
( groans )
I could have sworn that injector
was depolarized.
I guess I'm getting a little punchy.
When's the last time you've slept?
I got a full hour last night.
I'm surprised the neuropressure
isn't helping.
T'Pol told me
your first treatment went well.
Well, we only had the one session.
Haven't had a lot of free time lately.
Are you certain that's the reason?
What do you mean?
Vulcan neuropressure requires
a certain degree of intimacy.
I can understand that it might
make you, uh, uncomfortable.
It doesn't make me uncomfortable.
I just can't afford to spend
an hour every night in T'Pol's quarters.
Can't you just give me
another one of those injections?
They put me out like a light.
They're not meant to be taken
for extended periods.
There is another treatment
that might be helpful.
All right. What have you got?
Aldebaran mud leeches.
What am I supposed to do with them?
Place one on your chest
and one on your abdomen
an hour before going to bed.
Their secretions act
as a natural sedative.
Oh, uh, please...
Be careful to sleep on your back.
If you roll over, you might anger them.
Maybe an hour a night with T'Pol
isn't so bad.
The search teams have found
nearly 80% of our antimatter.
They're looking for the rest.
Probably running through
the reactor of that Osaarian ship.
We've also recovered most of our weapons.
How's Trip doing?
He'll have warp drive online
within the next 30 minutes.
Have the away team speed it up.
I want to go to warp
as soon as they're back.
Quantum scans indicate
it's nearly 1,000 years old.
What else?
The structure contains
seven fusion reactors.
Each one is almost 12 kilometers long.
Only three are still operational.
Any idea what they were designed for?
The sphere is emitting massive
amounts of gravimetric energy.
It may have something to do
with the spatial anomalies.
Take as many scans as you can.
-( beeps )
-Bridge to Captain Archer.
Go ahead.
Sir, could you come
to the situation room?
While I was translating
the cargo manifest,
something caught my eye.
Look at these markings.
I had to double-check,
but I was pretty sure
that I had seen this ideography before.
This is a piece of the Xindi probe
that crashed on Earth.
At least three of the symbols
are an exact match.
( beeps )
Your ship attacked a Xindi vessel.
I want to know everything
you can tell me about them.
Xindi?
You heard me.
I don't remember a species with that name.
You're lying!
The manifest said you took their ship
less than two weeks ago!
-What manifest?
-Tell me what you know.
It was a small ship.
They were no match for us.
Where are they now?
( snorts )
You destroyed them?
They resisted. We had no choice.
Where did they come from?
I have better things to do
than familiarize myself with our victims.
Which species of Xindi were they?
-What did they look like?
-I don't remember.
( beeps )
Are you sure?
Your threats aren't very convincing.
I told you, you're too civilized.
We'll see about that.
-Sir?
-As you were.
Ensign.
Are you taking me to your torture chamber?
Shut up.
Get in.
( beeps )
The Xindi.
This tactic doesn't suit you, Captain.
This airlock has a decompression rate
of 0.5 atmospheres per minute.
( beeps )
You'd better start talking now.
Because in about 40 seconds
you won't be able to.
( gasping )
The Xindi.
Captain?
Everything's under control, Lieutenant.
The airlock's decompressing, sir.
-( gasping )
-He'll die.
Not for another 20 seconds, he won't.
The Xindi.
-Sir?
-Your memory getting any better?
-( gasping )
-Say again?
Captain.
-( beeping )
-( gasping )
Take him back to the brig.
Let's go.
Was he cooperative?
Eventually.
When they attacked the Xindi ship,
they took more than fuel and supplies.
They downloaded their database.
How close would we have to get
to tap into their main computer?
Pretty close. Less than a kilometer.
But we need to have the access codes.
He gave them to me. Here.
They are heavily armed.
Are you sure it's wise to engage them?
I want that database.
Go to tactical alert.
Tell Trip we're gonna need
all the power he can spare
for weapons and hull plating.
Their ion trail's
already started to decay.
They're going to be hard to find.
We're gonna wait for them to find us,
Travis.
( beeping )
Something's passing
through the cloaking field.
Move us into position. Stand by.
Have they detected us?
Not yet.
Open a channel.
-( beeps )
-Go ahead.
This is Captain Archer. Remember us?
You've probably noticed that
our weapons are back online.
You're out-gunned. So stand down.
( explosion )
They're moving off.
One kilometer, Travis. Get ready.
-( explosion )
-Hull plating's holding.
They're heading back
into the cloaking field.
Stay with them.
Hoshi?
We're not close enough.
Stand by.
Another 50 meters.
I'm into the computer.
( beeping )
Anything?
I haven't found the Xindi database.
( rumbling )
I'm losing them.
Travis!
Forward hull plating is off-line.
I found it, Captain.
-How long do you need?
-A few minutes.
Hull fracture on "E" deck, section 14.
We're venting atmosphere.
Emergency bulkheads.
They're getting too far away.
I'm losing the com link again.
Our impulse drive's destabilizing.
We've got to get out
of the cloaking field, sir.
Head back to the sphere.
-Where are they?
-Still inside the field.
How much did you get?
About a third of it.
Take us closer to that portal.
Let's see if we can
lure them back in here.
Use our forward phase cannon.
Fire a single burst, minimum yield.
-Travis?
-No sign of them.
Again.
That got their attention.
They're coming through.
Stay within a kilometer. Return fire.
I'm back in.
Can you take out their engines?
Not without risking damage
to their main computer.
Ensign.
I've got 80%.
85%.
Hull plating's off-line.
They're targeting our reactor.
I've got 90%.
Good enough. Mr. Reed.
Their engines are down.
Keep our weapons locked on them.
Your codes worked.
Get him out of there.
Now that I've served my purpose,
you're taking me back to the airlock?
Escort him to the launch bay.
We're taking you back to the sphere.
So you have let your morality
get in the way after all.
( chuckles )
Mercy is not a quality
that will serve you well
in the expanse, Captain.
-Computer...
-( beeps )
Load the Xindi database.
( beeping )