[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SNARLING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ DOORBELL CHIMES ]
COME IN.
THANKS FOR SEEING ME SO LATE.
YOU SURE I'M NOT BOTHERING YOU?
NOT AT ALL.
GEORGIA PEACHES.
I PICKED UP A CRATE
WHEN WE WERE BACK ON EARTH.
CHEF'S BEEN KEEPING THEM
IN STASIS FOR ME.
THEY'RE AS FRESH
AS THE DAY THEY WERE PICKED.
THANK YOU.
AREN'T YOU GONNA TRY ONE?
I DON'T USUALLY EAT THIS LATE.
COME ON.
ONE BITE?
HUH?
THIS DOESN'T MAKE UP FOR
THE TWO SESSIONS YOU CANCELLED.
MAYBE YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
BUT I'VE BEEN
A LITTLE BUSY LATELY.
IT'S NOT LIKE
I DIDN'T WANT TO COME BACK.
AFTER OUR LAST SESSION,
I SLEPT LIKE A BABY.
FIRST TIME IN MONTHS.
[ SIGHS ]
SO SHOULD I JUST...
PLEASE.
-YOUR SHOES AS WELL.
-SHOES?
THERE ARE MANY NEURAL NODES
IN THE SOLES OF THE FEET.
HOLD ON. YOU NEVER
SAID ANYTHING ABOUT FEET.
IS THAT A PROBLEM?
WELL, FOR ONE THING, I HAVEN'T
HAD A SHOWER SINCE THIS MORNING,
AND I KNOW HOW SENSITIVE THAT
VULCAN NOSE OF YOURS CAN BE.
AND I'M A LITTLE TICKLISH.
MAYBE MORE THAN A LITTLE.
I'LL STOP AT THE FIRST SIGN
OF DISCOMFORT.
YEAH.
[ SIGHS ]
OH!
YOUR HANDS ARE ICE-COLD.
LONG, DEEP BREATHS.
[ BREATHING DEEPLY ]
YOU SURE THIS IS SAFE?
I MEAN, HAS ANYONE EVER TRIED IT
ON A HUMAN BEFORE?
NOT TO MY KNOWLEDGE.
THE RISK OF PARALYSIS
IS MINIMAL.
BREATHE.
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
OH, THAT'S THE SPOT.
[ BEEPS ]
-T'POL.
-It's the captain.
I'd like you to join me in
the command center right away.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
-SORRY IF I WOKE YOU.
-I WASN'T ASLEEP.
LOOK AT THIS.
ANOTHER SPECIES OF XINDI?
ACCORDING TO PHLOX,
THEY PROBABLY EVOLVED
FROM SOME FORM
OF ARBOREAL PRIMATE.
I MANAGED TO PIECE TOGETHER
SOME OF THEIR STAR CHARTS.
IT TOOK ME HALF THE NIGHT
TO FIGURE OUT
HOW THEY MAP COORDINATES,
BUT I'VE BEEN ABLE
TO RECONSTRUCT
THE SHIP'S COURSE
OVER THE PAST FEW MONTHS.
THIS IS THE LAST PLANET
THEY VISITED
BEFORE THEY WERE ATTACKED
BY THE MARAUDERS.
DOES IT SAY
WHAT THEY WERE DOING THERE?
NO.
BUT IT'S ONLY A DAY AWAY.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THESE XINDI
WERE INVOLVED
WITH THE ONES
WHO ATTACKED EARTH.
WE DON'T KNOW THEY WEREN'T.
TELL TRAVIS TO SET A COURSE.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
THE ECOSYSTEM IS PROLIFIC.
THERE ARE SEVERAL MILLION
CHROMOPHYLLIC PLANT SPECIES
ALONE.
WHAT ABOUT XINDI?
I'M NOT DETECTING
ANY HUMANOID LIFE.
BUT IT'LL TAKE SEVERAL
HOURS TO SEARCH ALL
OF THE LAND MASSES.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN, I'M PICKING UP
A METALLIC SIGNATURE
AT THE NORTHERN END
OF THOSE EQUATORIAL ISLANDS.
IT LOOKS LIKE A LANDING CRAFT.
ANY BIO-SCANS?
NONE WITHIN
A 30-KILOMETER RADIUS.
ANOTHER 13 KILOMETERS.
THERE'S A BREAK IN THE CANOPY.
IT SHOULD BE WIDE ENOUGH.
I SEE IT.
SIR.
JUDGING BY THE OXIDATION, THIS
HAPPENED ABOUT TWO WEEKS AGO.
RIGHT ABOUT THE TIME
THE XINDI WERE HERE.
IT'S DEFINITELY ONE OF THEIRS.
I RECOGNIZE IT
FROM THE DATABASE.
SEARCH THE AREA.
SEE WHAT ELSE YOU CAN FIND.
SOME OF THEIR DATA BANKS
MAY STILL BE INTACT.
CAPTAIN!
A BODY.
-[ BEEPING ]
-IT ISN'T XINDI.
AT LEAST NOT ONE OF THE THREE
SPECIES WE'RE FAMILIAR WITH.
MAYBE IT WAS
ONE OF THE OTHER TWO.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
-[ BEEPING ]
-THE READINGS ARE THE SAME.
THIS WHOLE AREA'S
BEEN SCORCHED.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
I NEVER MUCH CARED
FOR THE TROPICS.
KEEP LOOKING.
LIEUTENANT?
[ HISSES ]
[ CHITTERS ]
[ CHITTERING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROANING ]
CAPTAIN!
T'POL TO ENTERPRISE.
-GO AHEAD.
-Send a security team
to the surface.
We're being altered
by some kind of --
[ Speaking native language ]
SUBCOMMANDER?
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
STAY BACK.
[ SHOUTING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ CHOKING ]
[ SNARLS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
CAPTAIN --
UNTIE ME.
LET ME GO.
[ CHITTERING ]
[ SNARLING ]
THANK YOU.
[ SNIFFING ]
[ CHITTERING ]
WE HAVE TO GET BACK
TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE?
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
MAY I HAVE THAT?
-[ HISSES ]
-THE DEVICE.
MAY I HAVE IT?
[ SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ CHITTERING ]
THIS MAY HELP US
UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TALK.
TALK.
YOU NEED TO TALK.
THAT'S A VULCAN BIO-SIGN.
I'M CERTAIN OF IT.
BUT THESE AREN'T HUMAN.
DEFINITELY NOT.
THEN WHERE'S
THE REST OF OUR TEAM?
THE ONLY REASON I DON'T
HAVE A SEARCH PARTY
DOWN THERE RIGHT NOW
IS BECAUSE YOU NEEDED MORE TIME
TO ANALYZE THE DATA.
NOW, UNLESS YOU CAN GIVE ME
A DAMN GOOD REASON
TO WAIT AROUND...
WHEN T'POL CALLED THE SHIP,
SHE SAID SOMETHING
WAS HAPPENING TO THEM.
SHE SAID THEY WERE
BEING ALTERED.
IT'S POSSIBLE
SHE WAS SPEAKING LITERALLY.
SOMETHING ON THE PLANET
MAY HAVE TRANSFORMED THEM,
UH, PHYSIOLOGICALLY.
YOU'RE SAYING THESE ALIEN
BIO-SIGNS COULD BE OUR PEOPLE?
FROM WHAT WE'VE SEEN
OF THE EXPANSE,
IT'S A POSSIBILITY
WE HAVE TO CONSIDER.
THE LAWS OF BIOCHEMISTRY
ON THIS WORLD
MAYBE JUST AS UNPREDICTABLE
AS THE LAWS OF PHYSICS.
WHOEVER THEY ARE,
THEY'RE NOT STAYING PUT.
THEY'RE HEADING DUE EAST
OF THE LANDING SITE.
-PREP SHUTTLEPOD 2.
-AYE, SIR.
I'D LIKE A LITTLE MORE TIME
TO STUDY THESE READINGS.
WE'LL USE E.V. SUITS
WITH BIOHAZARD PROTOCOLS.
HAVE THE DECON CHAMBER READY
WHEN WE GET BACK.
ENTERPRISE?
YES.
IT'S YOUR SHIP.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME FOR THIS.
WE HAVE TO FIND URQUAT.
IT'S ALL THAT MATTERS NOW.
URQUAT?
WE HAVE TO KEEP LOOKING.
IT'S SOMEWHERE CLOSE.
WHY ARE YOU TALKING TO HER?
SHE'S TRYING TO DELAY US.
OUR PEOPLE ARE THERE.
THEY CAN HELP US,
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED,
WHY WE CAN'T REMEMBER.
CAPTAIN, THAT DEVICE,
I CAN USE IT TO CALL ENTERPRISE.
YOU HAVE A DOCTOR ON BOARD.
HE CAN PROVE TO YOU
WHAT I'M SAYING IS TRUE.
DON'T TRUST HER.
SHE'S NOT ONE OF US.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE IS.
URQUAT.
[ GROWLS SOFTLY ]
YOU SAID WE NEED
TO FIND URQUAT.
WE SHOULD KEEP SEARCHING.
IT CAN'T BE FAR.
[ CHITTERING ]
[ GROWLS ]
[ SNARLS ]
[ SNIFFS ]
NO, THANK YOU.
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
[ CHITTERING ]
THEY'RE ABOUT THREE KILOMETERS
EAST OF US.
WE DON'T HAVE TOO MANY OPTIONS
FOR A LANDING SITE.
HOPE YOU BOYS ARE UP
FOR A LITTLE WALK.
[ WHIRRING ]
IT'S A SHUTTLEPOD
FROM ENTERPRISE.
THEY WON'T HURT YOU.
LET ME TALK TO THEM.
[ BEEPING ]
KEEP YOUR WEAPONS ON STUN.
CIRCLE AROUND.
[ BEEPING ]
[ CHITTERING ]
CHANG.
CAPTAIN!
WAIT!
DON'T YOU RECOGNIZE HIM?
TAKE LIEUTENANT REED
BACK TO SICK BAY.
-WHAT ABOUT YOU?
-I'M STAYING WITH THEM.
SUBCOMMANDER!
[ SNARLING ]
[ CHITTERING ]
HE DIDN'T EVEN RECOGNIZE ME.
DON'T BE OFFENDED.
IN HIS CURRENT CONDITION, I
DOUBT HE'D RECOGNIZE ANY OF US.
ANY IDEA WHAT CAUSED THIS?
A MUTAGENIC VIRUS.
HIS BLOOD WAS SWARMING
WITH THEM.
IT WAS APPARENTLY DESIGNED
TO REWRITE THE DNA OF ITS HOST
TO TRANSFORM ANY HUMANOID
IT INFECTS INTO ANOTHER SPECIES.
WHY DID IT HAVE
SO LITTLE EFFECT ON T'POL?
VULCAN "K" CELLS.
THEY SEEM TO NEUTRALIZE
THE PATHOGEN.
I'VE BEEN SYNTHESIZING
AN ANTIVIRUS
USING T'POL'S GENETIC PROFILE,
BUT I'M GOING TO NEED
AN ACTIVE SAMPLE OF HER DNA
TO COMPLETE IT.
WE NEED TO GET HER BACK
TO THE SHIP AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
I'M DOING MY BEST.
-[ BEEPS ]
-Bridge to Commander Tucker.
GO AHEAD.
Two ships just
dropped out of warp, sir.
They're on an intercept course.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY'RE HAILING US.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
YOUR SHIP IS
IN RESTRICTED SPACE.
SORRY.
IT WASN'T VERY WELL MARKED.
OUR SCANS INDICATE THAT ONE OF
THE PEOPLE ON YOUR SHIP
HAS BEEN INFECTED
WITH A DANGEROUS VIRUS.
WE'RE AWARE OF THAT.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU CAN TELL US ABOUT --
YOUR VESSEL
IS UNDER QUARANTINE.
PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
NO ONE'S COMING ABOARD
UNLESS I SAY SO.
THE INFECTED ORGANISM
MUST BE ERADICATED
BEFORE THE VIRUS CAN SPREAD.
THAT INFECTED ORGANISM
IS A MEMBER OF MY CREW.
DOES HE STILL LOOK LIKE
ONE OF YOUR CREW?
DOES HE RECOGNIZE YOU OR EVEN
SPEAK YOUR LANGUAGE ANYMORE?
WE'VE BEEN STUDYING THE MUTAGEN
FOR 60 YEARS.
THE ONLY COURSE OF ACTION
IS TO NEUTRALIZE THE OUTBREAK.
THERE ISN'T ANY OUTBREAK.
LIEUTENANT REED IS
IN MEDICAL ISOLATION.
WE WON'T ALLOW YOUR VESSEL
TO LEAVE ORBIT
WITH THE CONTAGION ABOARD.
LOOK, WE'VE ONLY BEEN DEALING
WITH THIS VIRUS FOR ONE DAY.
SO FORGIVE ME IF I DON'T
TAKE YOUR WORD FOR IT
THAT THE ONLY OPTION IS TO
NEUTRALIZE OUR TACTICAL OFFICER.
YOU WANT TO COME OVER TO DISCUSS
THE SITUATION, FINE.
BUT IF YOU TRY TO FORCE YOUR WAY
ONTO THIS SHIP,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE ONE HELL
OF A FIGHT ON YOUR HANDS.
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
[ GASPS ]
HOW LONG WAS I ASLEEP?
ONLY FOR A FEW MINUTES.
I SAW IT.
IN MY DREAM, I WAS THERE.
URQUAT?
OUR CITY.
THERE ARE NO CITIES
ON THIS PLANET.
YOU'RE WRONG.
IT'S BELOW THE SURFACE.
TELL ME.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE?
IT WAS FILLED
WITH THOUSANDS OF LOQUE'EQUE.
WAITING.
FOR US.
YOUR HOME
IS A PLANET CALLED EARTH.
THE PEOPLE THERE
ARE WAITING FOR YOU.
YOU'RE ON A MISSION
TO SAVE THEM.
URQUAT'S MY HOME.
WHEN WE GET THERE,
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
WAIT AND SEE.
WE'VE RESTED LONG ENOUGH.
THE DECON CHAMBER IS SEALED.
I ASSURE YOU,
THERE'S NO DANGER.
YOU WOULDN'T BE SO CONFIDENT
IF YOU KNEW HOW EASILY
THIS VIRUS CAN SPREAD.
IT INFECTED TENS OF MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE ON MY WORLD.
THEY ALL HAD TO BE DESTROYED.
DESTROYED?
THE VIRUS WOULD HAVE TRANSFORMED
OUR ENTIRE POPULATION
WITHIN WEEKS.
WHERE DID IT COME FROM?
IT WAS ENGINEERED BY
THE INHABITANTS OF THIS PLANET,
A RACE CALLED THE LOQUE'EQUE.
SOMETHING DECIMATED
THEIR SPECIES CENTURIES AGO,
AND THEY LOST THE ABILITY
TO REPRODUCE.
SO THEY CREATED THIS VIRUS
TO TRANSFORM OTHER SPECIES
INTO THEIR OWN.
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY TO SAVE
THEMSELVES FROM EXTINCTION.
INGENIOUS.
BUT WHY DIDN'T THEY PROGRAM
THE VIRUS TO STOP REPLICATING
ONCE THEIR POPULATION
WAS REPLENISHED?
WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION FOR A LONG TIME.
WHY'S HE SO EAGER TO GET BACK
TO A PLACE CALLED URQUAT?
THE MUTAGEN ENCODES THE VICTIMS
WITH AN OVERPOWERING INSTINCT
TO RETURN
TO THEIR HOME CITY, URQUAT.
THAT'S WHY WE CAN'T ALLOW
EVEN A SINGLE INFECTED ORGANISM
TO LEAVE THIS PLANET.
THEY COULD SPREAD THE CONTAGION
TO OTHER SYSTEMS,
AND ANYONE WHO BECAME INFECTED
WOULD BE DRAWN BACK HERE.
WE CAN'T RISK ANOTHER EPIDEMIC.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
YES?
We've detected three more
infected organisms
on the surface.
PREPARE A CONTAINMENT TEAM.
MORE OF YOUR CREWMEN?
ONE OF THEM HAS AN IMMUNITY
TO THE VIRUS.
IF I COULD HAVE ACCESS
TO SOME OF YOUR RESEARCH,
PERHAPS WE COULD WORK TOGETHER.
WE'LL FIND THESE PEOPLE
AND EXAMINE THEM.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING TO REPORT,
WE'LL LET YOU KNOW.
I'D PREFER TO HAVE
DR. PHLOX EXAMINE THEM.
WHAT YOU PREFER DOESN'T MATTER.
I'M UNDER ORDERS
TO CONTAIN THIS OUTBREAK.
IF YOU ATTEMPT TO INTERFERE,
I'M AUTHORIZED TO USE
ANY FORCE NECESSARY.
TAKE ME BACK TO THE AIRLOCK.
IF I DON'T COMPLETE
THE ANTIVIRUS
WITHIN THE NEXT TWO HOURS,
IT'LL BE TOO LATE.
THERE WON'T BE ENOUGH
OF THEIR ORIGINAL GENOME LEFT
TO RESEQUENCE.
WE CAN'T LAUNCH A SHUTTLEPOD.
THEY'D DETECT IT.
[ SIGHS ]
DO YOU THINK T'POL'S CONTAGIOUS?
MOST LIKELY.
THAT RULES OUT THE TRANSPORTER.
SHE'D INFECT THE ENTIRE CREW.
WHATEVER YOU DO, COMMANDER,
DO IT QUICKLY.
I NEED THAT DNA SAMPLE.
BE RIGHT BACK.
-[ BEEPS ]
-Bridge to Commander Tucker.
GO AHEAD.
One of those ships
just launched a shuttle, sir.
It's heading toward the surface.
KEEP AN EYE ON 'EM.
[ PANTING ]
IT ISN'T FAR NOW.
THE PASSAGE WAS HERE
IN MY DREAM.
HELP ME.
YOU SAID THEY'D BE
WAITING FOR US.
I...SAW IT...
SO C-CLEARLY.
THERE WAS...A FOUNTAIN THERE.
AND GARDENS.
UP THERE.
FLOATING.
AND THERE WERE...PEOPLE.
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE!
COME BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
WE'LL HELP YOU FIND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR CITY.
NO! NO!
WE'RE NOT LEAVING.
THIS IS OUR HOME.
HOME. HOME.
LOOK AROUND.
THESE RUINS ARE ANCIENT.
NO ONE HAS LIVED HERE
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
WHAT ABOUT THIS?
THIS BODY ISN'T ANCIENT.
SOMEONE KILLED THEM.
WHY?
WHO WOULD DO THIS?
YOUR PEOPLE?
-NO.
-THEN WHO?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT IF WE GO TO ENTERPRISE,
WE CAN TRY TO FIND OUT.
I DON'T BELONG ON ENTERPRISE!
I BELONG HERE.
SOMEONE'S COMING.
MORE OF YOUR HUMANS?
I DON'T THINK SO.
WE'RE NOT SAFE HERE.
COME.
WE MUST GO.
COME. WE MUST GO.
WE FOUND THEM.
Take the Vulcan woman.
Then destroy the others.
UNDERSTOOD.
WHO ARE THEY?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU DESTROYED MY CITY!
KILLED MY PEOPLE!
[ GAS HISSING ]
CAPTAIN!
WE HAVE TO GET
TO THE SURFACE.
THIS WAY.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
NO. NO.
NO.
NO!
[ SCREAMING ]
LOWER YOUR WEAPON AND MOVE AWAY.
YOU WON'T BE HARMED.
I SAID MOVE AWAY!
AAH!
[ SNARLS ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YOU SAID YOU'D NEVER
USE THE TRANSPORTER AGAIN.
BELIEVE ME,
I WISH I'D HAD A CHOICE.
THERE ARE MORE OF THEM IN ORBIT.
WE'D BETTER GET BACK
TO THE SHUTTLEPOD
BEFORE THEY REALIZE
ANYTHING'S WRONG.
CAPTAIN.
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE.
YOU'LL BE SAFE ON ENTERPRISE.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S COMMANDER TUCKER.
PUT HIM THROUGH.
GO AHEAD, SIR.
We're docking, Travis.
Tell Phlox to stand by in decon.
Go to warp 4
as soon as we're in.
UNDERSTOOD.
REPORT.
THEY'RE IN PURSUIT.
2,000 KILOMETERS AND CLOSING.
TRY TO STAY AHEAD OF 'EM.
STAND BY WEAPONS.
THEY'RE HAILING US.
DON'T RESPOND.
HOLD YOUR COURSE.
900 KILOMETERS.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS!
700.
[ EXPLOSION ]
FULL POWER TO AFT HULL PLATING!
HULL PLATING'S DOWN TO 40%.
-[ BEEPING ]
-WE'RE BEING HAILED AGAIN.
DROP OUT OF WARP.
LOOK, WE BOTH WANT
THE SAME THING --
A CURE FOR THIS VIRUS, RIGHT?
OUR DOCTOR THINKS
HE'S FOUND ONE,
BUT HE NEEDS
A LITTLE MORE TIME.
I WON'T WARN YOU AGAIN,
COMMANDER.
WE'RE GOING TO
CONTAIN THIS OUTBREAK
WHETHER YOU COOPERATE OR NOT.
WHY ARE YOU FIRING
AT MY SHIP?
THERE ARE THREE INFECTED PEOPLE
ON BOARD.
WE WON'T ALLOW YOU
TO LEAVE THIS SYSTEM.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER
AND ENSIGN SATO.
THEY'RE THE PEOPLE YOU NEARLY
INCINERATED ON THAT PLANET.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
THEY'RE RESPONDING QUITE WELL
TO THE ANTIVIRUS I SYNTHESIZED.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
RUN SCANS.
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
LIKE I SAID, HE JUST NEEDED
A LITTLE MORE TIME.
I'M SURE WE'D BE HAPPY TO SHARE
THE ANTIVIRUS WITH YOU.
BUT THAT'LL BE IMPOSSIBLE
IF YOU DESTROY OUR SHIP.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE GIVEN PHLOX'S SERUM
TO THE CAPTAIN
OF THE CONTAINMENT VESSEL.
WITH ANY LUCK,
THEY'LL BE ABLE TO USE IT
TO PREVENT FUTURE OUTBREAKS.
AS FOR MALCOLM, HOSHI, AND ME,
IT MAY BE A FEW DAYS BEFORE
WE FEEL FULLY HUMAN AGAIN.
[ CLICKS ]
THIS SHOULD HELP
WITH THE HEADACHES.
HAVE YOU GOT ANYTHING
FOR MY STOMACH?
CHEF'S FOOD
ISN'T SITTING TOO WELL.
TILL YOUR DIGESTIVE TRACT
IS FULLY RESTORED,
YOU MAY WANT TO AVOID
THE MESS HALL.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST I EAT?
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO SOME OF THE MOTH LARVAE
I FEED MY PYRITHIAN BAT.
[ GRUNTS ]
HOW ARE YOU FEELING,
LIEUTENANT?
NOT BAD, SIR.
HOW ABOUT YOURSELF?
GETTING THERE.
HOSHI AND T'POL
ARE GONNA TAKE THE DAY OFF.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO DO THE SAME.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I COULD USE A LITTLE REST.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME?
THIS IS THE LAST
OF THE MUTAGENIC VIRUS.
I ASSUME YOU WANT ME
TO DESTROY IT.
NO.
CAPTAIN,
YOU EXPERIENCED FIRSTHAND
WHAT THIS PATHOGEN CAN DO.
THOSE CONTAINMENT PATROLS
AREN'T GOING TO STOP
UNTIL THEY'VE WIPED OUT
EVERY TRACE OF IT.
NOW THAT THEY HAVE
YOUR ANTIVIRUS,
THEY'LL MOST LIKELY FIGURE OUT
A WAY TO SUCCEED.
CONSIDERING THE ALTERNATIVES,
THAT WOULD BE BEST.
THIS WAS CREATED
AS A FINAL EFFORT
TO PRESERVE A CIVILIZATION,
A-A PEOPLE.
THAT SPECIES WE BECAME...
...THEY CEASE TO EXIST
THE MOMENT THIS VIRUS IS GONE.
CAPTAIN...
WE CAME OUT HERE TO STOP THE
XINDI FROM DESTROYING HUMANITY.
I'LL BE DAMNED
IF I'M GONNA HAVE A HAND
IN DESTROYING ANOTHER RACE
IN THE PROCESS.
PUT IT ON ICE, DOC.
IN STASIS, WHATEVER.
UNDERSTOOD?