How much of the lab was destroyed?
Nearly all of it.
Three of my researchers were killed.
And what of your work, Degra?
I haven't been able to assess
how much data was lost.
This will obviously delay us.
( clicking )
Months, perhaps. I'm not certain.
They attacked a trellium mine.
We cannot wait any longer.
Think what you're asking me to do!
Build a weapon to destroy an entire world.
Do you understand how difficult,
how dangerous, this project is?
Are you saying you're not up to the task?
( screeching )
I agree. We are too far along
to change our plan.
Besides, we have no alternative.
You know that isn't true.
That option has been
discussed and rejected.
( clicking )
Perhaps it is time to reconsider
our colleagues' proposal.
We do not have enough information
about the humans.
That can be remedied.
( screeching )
I agree.
( scoffs )
Degra deserves more time.
( screeching )
Is that sufficient pressure?
You could go a little harder.
Mmm, perfect.
Try that neck thing. What do you call it?
-The Khavorta posture?
-Yeah. That one.
Are you certain?
Don't worry.
I've been practicing my breathing.
( inhaling deeply )
You have been practicing.
T'Pol...
Don't speak.
Relax your jaw.
Excellent.
Now the Surah'than.
You know, I really need
to talk to you about something.
Is there a problem?
No. No, no. I mean, this feels great
And I really appreciate you
taking the time.
It's just...
I'm not sure we should be
doin' it anymore.
You said this was helping you sleep.
It has.
Then why do you want to stop?
People are talking.
About us.
About me coming to your quarters at night.
They think there's more going on
than neuro-pressure.
And that disturbs you?
It shouldn't, I know, but...
Malcolm and I were purging
a clogged injector assembly last week,
and he asked me why
I didn't just massage it
with my magic fingers.
I see no reason to be
concerned with idle gossip.
It doesn't bother you?
We're both senior officers.
If we were pursuing
a romantic relationship,
it wouldn't be Lieutenant Reed's concern,
would it?
I suppose not.
Shall we continue?
( chuckles )
( Archer murmuring )
( grunting )
( sighing )
PHLOX: You've been scratching again.
The itching kept me up all night.
Have you been using the ointment
I gave you?
I tried, but the smell is...
is a little strong.
The more you scratch,
the longer it will take to heal.
I understand you may have
found a source of trellium-D?
A V'radian chemist we met
at the deuterium station
claims he knows a way to synthesize it.
I hope he's correct.
Crewman Cutler broke her arm
when one of those spatial anomalies
went through the exobiology lab.
The sooner the ship is insulated
against these phenomena,
the happier I will be.
-We're working on it, Doctor.
-Of course.
Have you, uh, had any other symptoms?
Just, um...
( groaning )
Dreams.
I keep...
seeing myself back at that alien city.
You were transformed
into a different species.
Don't expect to recover overnight.
( indistinct talking )
The chemist said his shop
is on barge 12.
( creatures squawking )
Phlox would have a field day here.
I'm afraid we'll have to save
the souvenir hunting for another time.
I don't recognize your species.
You must be newcomers.
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
We're looking for barge 12,
a chemist named B'Rat Ud.
It would be a shame
if I let you leave our world
without introducing you
to the local wildlife.
T-that's not necessary.
Xanthan marmots make wonderful pets
and their flesh is quite succulent
when prepared properly.
No, thank you.
Can you dire-- direct us to the chemist?
Barge 12 is that way. Tier 2.
( Xanthan marmot chirping )
( door opens )
I'm closed.
I have an appointment.
We met at the deuterium station
on Norellus.
You'll have to come back later.
You said you could sell us the formula
to synthesize trellium-D.
I hope you didn't bring us
all this way for nothing.
Captain Archer. I remember now.
How are you?
-A little pressed for time.
-Of course.
Trellium-A is extremely common,
easy to synthesize,
but trellium-D is rare,
difficult to process.
And expensive?
I'm confident we can agree
on a fair price.
I was thinking about you recently,
Captain.
You were very eager to learn
about the Xindi, as I recall.
What is your interest in them?
We're on a diplomatic mission.
A diplomatic mission.
( chuckles )
Some Xindi arrived here last week.
I thought you might be interested.
Where can we find them?
They had business with another merchant.
Who?
I'd be happy to direct you
for a small fee.
Commander Tucker has the list
of supplies and equipment
we'd be willing to barter.
As a gesture of good faith,
why don't you tell me where
we can find this merchant,
then you and Mr. Tucker
can work out the details.
I'm confident we can agree
on a fair price.
( aliens chattering )
FEMALE: Do you like what you see?
To answer your first question,
I regret I cannot offer free samples.
B'Rat Ud said
you might be able to help us.
I always welcome referrals.
What is your pleasure?
We were told you've recently
done business with some Xindi.
Excellent customers.
They purchased two U'tani serpent women.
I'm afraid I don't have any more,
but perhaps I could interest you
in a nuvian concubine.
She's quite skilled.
We're not interested.
I want to know
where I can find these Xindi.
I believe they left orbit two days ago.
Where were they heading?
I wouldn't stay in business for very long
if I revealed
confidential information about my clients.
But I have females here from many worlds.
Who knows?
Perhaps one of them can tell you
what you want to know about the Xindi.
You have an excellent eye, my friend.
She can be very accommodating.
( communicator beeps )
Archer.
TUCKER: Captain, B'Rat and I
have agreed on a price.
I'll need to go back
to the ship for his payment.
Understood. We'll meet you
back at the shuttlepod.
How can you walk away from such beauty?
Thanks for your time.
After an hour in this place,
I can't wait to get back to decon.
-( crashing )
-MALE: Stop her!
MALE 2: Watch yourself!
Take me with you, please!
( panting )
She seems determined to be sold today.
Let's go back to my shop
and arrange for payment.
I don't think so.
Then I'll take my merchandise.
Looks like she doesn't want
to go with you.
If you're so concerned
about what she wants, buy her.
Otherwise, stay out of my business!
( grunting )
-Let's get out of here.
-Gladly.
You have the most intriguing eyes.
I've never seen a retinal structure
this complex.
( door opens )
How's our guest?
I'm not familiar with her species
but, uh, she appears to be
in perfect health.
I'm afraid I don't even know your name.
I'm called Rajiin.
Very grateful for what
you've done, Captain.
I'll serve you well, I promise.
Let's get something straight.
We don't believe one person
can own another person.
You're free to go wherever you'd like.
How far is your homeworld?
I don't know.
I'm told it's called Oran'taku,
but I don't remember it.
-Do you have any family?
-I've had many owners.
We have some data on this region of space.
I'll see if I can locate Oran'taku.
If it's possible, we'll take you there.
Set her up in quarters.
Get her whatever she needs.
Of course.
Captain.
Thank you.
On our planet,
wars were fought over these.
Mmm.
( chuckling )
Careful.
( snorting )
( sneezes )
( laughing )
What's this one called?
-Black pepper.
-Ooh!
There's paprika, mustard seed.
I'm partial to the cayenne myself.
I'm sure you'll find these all
very exotic.
I believe you have something for us?
Of course.
I've reviewed
your engineering specifications.
You appear to have the necessary equipment
to produce liquid trellium-D.
Liquid?
Trellium can only be synthesized
in a liquid state.
It's just as effective as the natural ore.
Then all we need is the recipe.
Uh, there is one thing.
Be sure to follow the protocols precisely.
Or?
Let's just say that in its liquid form,
trellium-D is extremely unstable.
( Zjod snorting, sneezing )
( laughing )
Ooh!
How are your accommodations?
Much better than I'm used to.
The last ship I was on,
I never left the cargo hold.
Except for a few visits
to the captain's quarters.
There are some restricted areas
on Enterprise.
Otherwise, feel free to look around.
Your crew won't mind?
I seriously doubt it.
-Are they all from Earth?
-Nearly all.
You met Dr. Phlox. He's from Denobula.
And my First Officer's a Vulcan.
Dr. Phlox mentioned you were
on an important mission.
We're trying to make contact
with a species called Xindi.
I don't suppose you know
anything about them?
Very little.
The two I saw looked reptilian,
and they weren't very pleasant.
At the time, I was just relieved
they weren't interested in me.
Why are you looking for them?
We're hoping to resolve a disagreement.
-( intercom beeps )
-Tucker to Captain Archer.
Archer.
We're in business, sir.
I'll be right there.
Excuse me.
( door closing )
ARCHER: How unstable?
Enough to do some serious damage
if we screw this up.
And we're supposed to insulate
the entire ship with it?
It's only volatile in its liquid form.
Once we apply it to the inner hull
and it sets, it's completely safe.
The tricky part's cookin' it up
in the first place.
It'll require extremely precise
calculations,
But I believe Mr. Tucker and I
can synthesize the compound safely.
Get started.
I recommend we set up
a lab on E-deck
within the emergency bulkheads,
as a precaution.
( sighing )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Good evening, Captain.
Is everything all right?
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I hoped you might have time to talk.
Um...
I'm, uh, not quite, uh...
Please.
I meant to speak with you earlier.
We have some good news.
T'Pol was able to locate your home planet
in a database we acquired.
It's only two days away.
You don't seem very pleased.
I was taken away when I was very young.
I don't remember much about it.
And I doubt anyone there
would remember me.
You never know.
You seem very memorable to me.
I'm very grateful for what you've done,
Captain.
I want to repay you for your kindness.
That isn't necessary.
I know.
Rajiin, you--
There's a reason I was taken from my home.
I have certain gifts.
Would you like me to show you?
That... really isn't something that--
It's all right.
( faint hissing )
Captain.
Is something wrong?
No.
Well, I just wanted to say
thank you again.
We'll be leaving orbit soon.
Good night.
( door chimes )
What's the molecular pressure?
Up to 1,100 units.
Boy, this stuff is tricky.
( beeping )
Decrease the theta bombardment
by 6%... No, 7%.
The pressure's still rising, 1,400 units.
1,430.
Damn it! ( sighs )
Kill the theta radiation altogether.
( beeping continues )
No effect.
We should seal off this section and leave.
A sustained burst of delta radiation
might do the trick.
And it might not. We should evacuate.
I'm going to ramp the delta to 80%.
It's not working.
You're welcome to leave.
The pressure is up to 2,000 units.
-( warning alarm beeping )
-Commander!
( coughs )
Some of our calculations
may have been slightly off.
We're back to square one.
( sighs )
We've been working for six hours.
I suggest we take a break.
I can't argue with that.
Come to my quarters in half an hour.
We'll resume your neuro-pressure regimen.
I'll be fine.
I'd prefer you were rested
before we make another attempt.
Can I help you?
The captain said it was all right
if I left my quarters.
-I'm Rajiin.
-I know.
News travels fast on a starship.
I'm Ensign Hoshi Sato.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I was looking for the mess hall.
I just happen to be going that way.
What's your job here?
I'm the ship's communications officer.
I see.
I'd love to hear your language.
Actually, I speak quite a few.
You must be T'Pol.
I didn't mean to startle you.
My name is Rajiin.
I know who you are.
What are you doing here?
Your door was unlocked.
That's not likely.
I was hoping we'd have a chance to talk.
Perhaps you are unfamiliar
with our protocols,
but it is unacceptable
for you to be in my quarters uninvited.
I didn't think you'd mind.
-I'm afraid--
-You're a Vulcan.
On a ship filled with humans.
Why?
Vulcans and humans are allies.
Now please leave.
-What are you doing?
-Don't resist.
I need you to leave.
You have a disciplined mind.
You're in such control of your emotions.
( whispers ) Try to let go.
( sighing deeply )
Better.
( breathes deeply )
Stop.
Let go.
( door chimes )
( chimes )
( gasps )
( grunts )
( both grunting )
No!
-( door chimes )
-No!
-( communicator beeps )
-Tucker to the bridge.
FEMALE: Go ahead.
Could you tell me where T'Pol is?
She's in her quarters, sir.
( beeping )
( grunts )
-( communicator beeps )
-Tucker to Security.
-I need assistance.
-MALE REPTILIAN: Were you successful?
I have what you want.
I can use their transporter device,
but you'll need to be
within 10,000 kilometers.
MALE REPTILIAN:
Signal us when you're ready.
Is there something wrong?
The captain would like to see you.
There's no need to bother the captain.
I have my orders.
So do I.
Shh.
( sighs )
( grunts )
Are you in range?
Respond!
Leaving so soon?
We jammed your signal.
Your friends can't hear you.
Who are they?
Take her to the brig.
You should let me run a neuro-scan.
I'll be fine.
What happened to her?
I can't even begin to speculate.
She's suffered disruptions
throughout her neocortex.
If she were human,
or Denobulan for that matter,
she'd probably be dead.
But Vulcan neurophysiology
is a great deal more resilient than ours.
I want to talk to her.
I have to finish
treating her injuries first.
-How long?
-A few hours.
Have Phlox take a look at your head.
( beep )
Who were you trying to contact?
I'm sorry.
-I asked you a question.
-I can't answer it.
What did you do to T'Pol?
She shouldn't have resisted.
Who are you?
I told you. My name is Rajiin.
That's right.
Kidnapped when you were a child,
sold into a life of slavery.
And it was just a coincidence
that you happened to escape
when I was at that market.
The chemist knew I was
looking for information about the Xindi.
Is that why you showed up so conveniently?
The only thing I can tell you
is that you're in danger.
Care to be a little more specific?
If I say anything else, they'll kill me.
Who? The Xindi?
How do you know I won't do the same?
It's true that I deceived you.
But that didn't make your decision
to help me any less admirable.
I don't want to see you harmed, Captain.
The best thing for you to do is let me go.
Tell me who you contacted.
Who?
-( intercom beeping )
-MALCOLM: Bridge to Captain Archer.
ARCHER: Go ahead.
MALCOLM: Two vessels
are approaching from aft.
Sir, the bio-signs
match the genetic profile
of the Xindi pilot who attacked Earth.
Hull plating to full power,
stand by weapons.
The reptilian species.
They're the ones who sent you.
I had no choice.
( rumbling )
We're dropping out of warp.
I assume they're here for you.
They won't harm anyone
if you let me go.
Forgive me if I don't
take your word on that,
but they murdered
seven million people on my planet.
-( intercom beeps )
-MALCOLM: Bridge to the captain.
Go ahead.
The smaller ship is approaching
the starboard docking port.
Seal that airlock and post security teams.
I'm on my way.
What was your mission?
-They wanted information.
-About what?
About you.
They're building a weapon.
We know that.
This is different.
A bio-weapon.
Go on.
They need data about your species
before they can begin.
Where are they building the weapon?
I don't know.
-When will it be ready?
-I don't know.
They didn't tell me anything else.
Get a security detail down here.
No one's taking her anywhere.
Fall back!
( grunts )
( groaning )
Three boarding parties,
at least five men each.
They're headin' for the brig.
Try to cut 'em off.
You're with me.
( grunts )
( all groaning )
( rattling )
( weapon fires )
( high-pitched beeping )
( grunting )
( grunts )
( panting )
( beeping )
-Archer to the bridge.
-TRAVIS: Go ahead.
Don't let those ships get away!
Lay in a pursuit course.
Aye, sir.
He's dead, sir.
-( intercom beeps )
-Captain.
Those ships just entered
some kind of vortex.
( beeping )
They're gone.
( panting )
This gland released
a fatal dose of neuro-toxin
into his bloodstream.
What kind of species is born
with a suicide gland?
Not this one. He was surgically enhanced,
if you can call it an enhancement.
I want a complete autopsy, Doctor.
And have Malcolm take this weapon apart.
I want to find out
its range, power output,
and how we can defend against it.
Aye, sir.
Are you OK?
Yes.
Good.
Because I want an analysis
of the scans we took of those Xindi ships
and find out what you can
about that vortex they went through.
I don't want them dropping in
unannounced again.
Dismissed.
You've put all of our work at risk.
And exposed us to the humans.
Allowed one of your soldiers
to be captured.
Ah! He wasn't taken alive.
You agreed to give me more time.
You don't have enough data
to construct the bio-weapon.
Don't we?
Bring her!
( footsteps approaching )
Show them.
Show them!
We couldn't pursue the bio-weapon
because we didn't have enough information
about the humans.
Now we do.
( screeching )
Do you expect us to reward you
for this act of insubordination?
This has left us more vulnerable
than we were before.
There's more to these humans
than you can learn
from a set of biometric scans.
That's enough!
Take her.