SHE'S COMING TO.
[ GROANS ]
LET ME GO!
-STOP!
-I'LL KILL YOU!
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HURT YOU!
YOU LIAR. NO!
GET AWAY FROM ME! NO!
[ SCREAMING ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
THE DAMAGE IS MORE SEVERE
THAN I EXPECTED.
-CAN YOU REVERSE IT?
-I'M NOT CERTAIN.
[ GRUNTING ]
-WHAT'S HE DOING?
-IT'S ALL RIGHT.
-HE'S TRYING TO HELP YOU.
-HE'S TRYING TO KILL ME!
LIKE YOU KILLED THE OTHERS!
MURDERERS!
GET AWAY!
NO!
[ SCREAMING ]
I TALKED WITH CHEF AT DINNER.
HE'S A LITTLE WORRIED
ABOUT THE CREW.
PEOPLE ARE SKIPPING MEALS.
HE FIGURES
THEY'RE EITHER TOO BUSY
OR THE STRESS OF THIS MISSION
IS STARTING TO GET TO THEM.
I HAVEN'T HAD
MUCH OF AN APPETITE MYSELF.
MOVIE NIGHT'S BEEN ON HOLD
SINCE WE ENTERED THE EXPANSE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
START IT UP AGAIN.
THERE'LL BE PLENTY OF TIME
FOR MOVIES
AFTER WE'VE DEALT
WITH THE XINDI.
NO ONE HATES THE XINDI
MORE THAN I DO, CAPTAIN.
BUT I'M TELLING YOU,
THIS CREW NEEDS A LITTLE R&amp;R.
UNLESS YOU WANT PHLOX TO START
MEDICATING PEOPLE, WE GOT TO...
WE GOT TO FIND A WAY
TO BOOST MORALE.
WHAT DID YOU HAVE IN MIND?
I WAS THINKING ABOUT A COMEDY.
ONE OF THE CLASSIC
HOPE AND CROSBY PICTURES.
GOOD CHOICE.
CAPTAIN?
WE'VE BEEN REVIEWING
SOME OF THESE XINDI STAR CHARTS.
TRIP THOUGHT THEY MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP US FIGURE OUT
IF THERE ARE ANY MORE
SPATIAL ANOMALIES IN THE REGION.
I WOULD HAVE HELPED YOU DO THAT.
IT'S LATE.
I DIDN'T WANT
TO GET YOU OUT OF BED.
BESIDES, OUR RESIDENT INSOMNIAC
WAS LOOKING FOR SOMETHING TO DO.
[ BEEPING ]
YOU HAVE PLANS TUESDAY NIGHT?
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
MESS HALL, 1900 HOURS.
MOVIE NIGHT?
BACK BY POPULAR DEMAND.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
GO AHEAD.
I'M PICKING UP AN AUTOMATED
DISTRESS CALL, SIR.
IT'S VULCAN.
HAVE YOU TRIED HAILING THEM?
SEVERAL TIMES.
I'M ON MY WAY.
WHERE ARE THEY?
3.2 LIGHT-YEARS,
BEARING 016 MARK 12.
I RECOGNIZE
THE TRANSPONDER FREQUENCY.
IT'S THE SELEYA.
THEY ENTERED THE EXPANSE
NINE MONTHS AGO.
KEEP HAILING THEM.
SET A COURSE.
THE ASTEROIDS ARE MOVING
IN A CHAOTIC FASHION.
THEIR PATHS ARE UNPREDICTABLE.
MAY BE THE RESULT
OF SOME SPATIAL ANOMALIES.
WHERE'S THE VULCAN SHIP?
APPROXIMATELY
2,000 KILOMETERS DEAD AHEAD.
I CAN GUESS WHY THEY WERE
INTERESTED IN THIS FIELD.
THE ASTEROIDS ARE LOADED
WITH TRELLIUM ORE.
IT LOOKS A LITTLE TOO CROWDED
IN THERE FOR ENTERPRISE.
WAKE UP MR. REED.
TELL HIM TO MEET US
IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
AYE, SIR.
TRY TO GET YOUR HANDS
ON SOME OF THAT ORE.
T'POL.
[ BEEPING ]
STARBOARD BOW, 340 METERS.
I SEE IT.
[ THUDDING ]
NO DAMAGE, THOUGH WE MAY NEED
A FRESH COAT OF PAINT.
HOW MUCH FARTHER?
1,200 KILOMETERS.
I COULD TAKE THE HELM
IF YOU'D LIKE.
MAYBE ON THE WAY BACK.
SO WHAT ELSE DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THE SELEYA?
A GREAT DEAL.
I SERVED ON IT FOR OVER A YEAR.
IT WAS MY LAST ASSIGNMENT
BEFORE JOINING
THE CONSULATE ON EARTH.
I WAS THE DEPUTY SCIENCE OFFICER
UNDER CAPTAIN VORIS.
ANY IDEA WHAT THEY
WERE DOING IN THE EXPANSE?
THEY WERE ATTEMPTING TO CHART
THE THERMOBARIC PERIMETER.
AFTER SEVERAL DAYS,
THEY REPORTED
THAT THEY'D BECOME CAUGHT
IN SOME KIND OF SUBSPACE EDDY
AND WERE BEING PULLED
INTO THE EXPANSE.
IT WAS THEIR FINAL TRANSMISSION.
THE VANKAARA
WAS SENT TO FIND THEM.
YOU ALREADY KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO THAT CREW.
LET'S HOPE THE SELEYA
FARED A LITTLE BETTER.
[ BEEPING ]
DIRECTLY AHEAD, 200 METERS.
HANG ON!
GOOD ISOTOPE DENSITY.
WE SHOULD GET AT LEAST
HALF A KILO OUT OF THIS ONE.
[ GRUNTS ] LET'S TRY FOR
SOMETHING BIGGER THIS TIME.
HOW ABOUT, UH, THIS ONE?
[ BEEPING ]
I'VE GOT A LOCK.
TRAVIS?
THERE'S AN OVERLOAD
IN THE RESEQUENCER.
SHUT IT DOWN.
I CAN'T.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
[ BUZZES ]
OH, THIS THING'S USELESS!
THE COILS ARE FUSED.
WHAT IF I COULD PUT A SHUTTLEPOD
DOWN ON ONE OF THE BIG ONES?
THEY'RE PRETTY UNPREDICTABLE.
YOU SURE YOU COULD LAND SAFELY?
I CAN TRY.
THIS'LL BE A NEW ONE
FOR THE MAINTENANCE CREW.
MAIN POWER'S OFFLINE.
THEIR HULL'S
TAKEN QUITE A BEATING.
LIFE SUPPORT?
MINIMAL. DECKS 12 AND 13
HAVE DECOMPRESSED.
I'M READING MULTIPLE BIOSIGNS.
[ BEEP ]
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
PLEASE RESPOND.
[ BEEP ]
SELEYA, COME IN.
THE STARBOARD DOCKING PORT
IS STILL INTACT.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN?
THEY WERE LINING THIS BULKHEAD
WITH TRELLIUM.
THEY DIDN'T GET VERY FAR.
I'M READING BIOSIGNS
ON THIS DECK.
I CAN'T ISOLATE THEM.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
TAKE STARBOARD.
VULCAN BLOOD.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ CLANKING ]
ONE BIOSIGN.
[ DOOR BUZZES ]
[ DOOR CLICKS ]
AAH!
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
UGH!
AAH!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
T'POL?
I'M FINE.
HIS SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS
HAVE BEEN SEVERELY DAMAGED.
LET'S GET HIM IN THE POD.
[ CLANK ]
CAPTAIN!
KEEP BACK.
ARCHER TO REED.
GO AHEAD, SIR.
HAVE YOU COME ACROSS ANYONE?
NOT YET.
WATCH YOURSELF.
SOMETHING'S HAPPENED TO THEM.
THEY'VE BECOME VIOLENT.
AYE, SIR.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANS ]
AAH!
UH!
[ CHOKING ]
[ GASPS ]
LIEUTENANT, YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM?
SEVEN MORE.
THAT DIRECTION. 30 METERS.
CAPTAIN.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[ GUN CLICKS ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
STUN ISN'T WORKING.
WE SHOULD SET OUR WEAPONS
TO KILL.
THESE ARE VULCAN OFFICERS,
AND WE'RE ON A RESCUE MISSION.
WITH RESPECT, MA'AM, THEY DON'T
SEEM TO WANT OUR HELP!
YOU HEARD ME.
KEEP YOUR WEAPONS ON STUN.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN, OVER HERE.
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
WE'RE FROM
THE STARFLEET SHIP ENTERPRISE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
[ GRUNTS ]
IS THERE ANOTHER WAY
TO THE AIRLOCK?
NO.
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
THAT WAY.
GO.
GO ON.
[ GRUNTS ]
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, RESPOND!
IF THEIR COM SYSTEM'S INTACT,
WE MAY BE ABLE TO CONTACT
ENTERPRISE FROM THE BRIDGE.
WHERE IS IT?
SEVEN DECKS ABOVE US.
SEVEN?
HOW MANY VULCANS ARE ON BOARD?
ASSUMING THE ENTIRE CREW
IS STILL ALIVE, 147.
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
THE LAUNCH BAY'S ON THIS LEVEL.
MAYBE WE CAN USE
ONE OF THEIR SHUTTLES.
THE BAY'S DEPRESSURIZED,
PROBABLY FROM
AN ASTEROID IMPACT.
WE HAVE TO GET BACK TO OUR POD.
THAT'LL BE DIFFICULT.
ALL FOUR BULKHEADS LEADING
TO THE AIRLOCK HAVE BEEN SEALED.
[ BANGING ]
WE SHOULD KEEP MOVING.
HOW'S YOUR ARM?
IT'S FINE, SIR.
HE'S LOSING A LOT OF BLOOD,
CAPTAIN.
WE'VE GOT TO TREAT THIS WOUND.
HOW FAR TO THEIR SICKBAY?
IT'S TWO DECKS UP.
LET'S GO.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
SINCE WE'VE COME ABOARD,
I'VE BEEN EXPERIENCING ANXIETY.
WHATEVER'S HAPPENED TO THIS CREW
MAY BE STARTING TO AFFECT ME.
WE'LL GET YOU OUT OF HERE
AS SOON AS WE CAN.
THIS ONE'S MORE ISOLATED.
AND I'M READING LARGE DEPOSITS
NEAR THE SURFACE.
CAN YOU SET US DOWN?
THERE ISN'T A FLAT SPOT
MUCH BIGGER THAN MY QUARTERS.
AH, YOU'RE THE PILOT.
IT'S YOUR CALL.
LET'S GO.
I'M MATCHING
THE ROTATIONAL VELOCITY.
LOOKING GOOD.
200 METERS.
YOU'RE DRIFTING TO THE LEFT.
GOT IT.
[ BEEPING ]
I HOPE YOU WON'T WRITE
THAT LANDING UP IN YOUR LOG.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
I'M GONNA RECOMMEND
THEY GIVE YOU A MEDAL.
LET'S TRY TO MAKE THIS QUICK.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANS ]
ANY IDEA WHAT'S CAUSING THIS?
I'M NOT A DOCTOR.
BUT YOU ARE MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
I NEED TO KNOW
I CAN DEPEND ON YOU.
I'LL DO MY BEST.
HIS NAME IS SOLIN.
WHEN I SERVED HERE,
HE WAS THE CHIEF ENGINEER.
I KNEW HIM.
[ GASPS ]
CAN YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
SUBCOMMANDER T'POL.
WE SERVED TOGETHER.
AAAAH!
DON'T YOU RECOGNIZE ME?
[ GROANING ]
WE'RE HERE TO HELP YOU,
BUT WE NEED TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR CREW.
[ GRUNTING ]
SOLIN, LOOK AT ME.
SOMETHING HAS MADE YOU VERY ILL.
YOU'VE LOST CONTROL.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
TELL ME!
[ GRUNTING ]
THIS IS GOING TO HAPPEN TO ME.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
IT'S ALREADY STARTED!
I CAN FEEL MY CONTROL
SLIPPING AWAY.
WE'RE GETTING YOU OFF THIS SHIP.
IT'S TOO LATE.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE THE SCANS
YOU MADE BACK TO PHLOX
AND FIGURE OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
BUT FIRST, WE HAVE TO
GET TO THE SHUTTLE.
HOW DO YOU OPEN THOSE BULKHEADS?
THE BULKHEADS.
THERE'S AN AUXILIARY CONTROL
ROOM ON THE ENGINEERING DECK.
OKAY.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
T'POL.
WE HAVE TO KEEP MOVING.
I DON'T NEED YOUR HELP.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
TWO MORE BIOSIGNS
50 METERS BEYOND THAT HATCH.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO THE ENGINEERING DECK.
WE'LL GO DEAL WITH THEM.
STAY WITH HER, HAWKINS.
AYE, SIR.
WATER?
NO OFFENSE, BUT YOU LOOK
LIKE YOU COULD USE SOME.
THANK YOU.
I APOLOGIZE FOR THE WAY
I REACTED BEFORE.
YOU WERE RIGHT,
THIS IS A RESCUE MISSION.
MAY I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
HOW IS IT POSSIBLE THAT
THIS CREW COULD TURN SO VIOLENT
WHEN VULCANS AREN'T
SUPPOSED TO HAVE EMOTIONS?
A COMMON MISCONCEPTION.
WE HAVE EMOTIONS.
WE SIMPLY KEEP THEM SUPPRESSED,
UNDER CONTROL.
SOMETHING HAS OBVIOUSLY CAUSED
THEM TO LOSE THAT CONTROL.
WHY WOULD THEY WANT TO KILL US?
THERE WAS A TIME IN THE PAST
WHEN WE WERE
AN EXTREMELY VIOLENT RACE.
WE NEARLY DESTROYED OURSELVES.
PARANOIA AND HOMICIDAL RAGE
WERE COMMON.
5 METERS.
[ GRUNTS ]
ANY MORE WHERE THEY CAME FROM?
[ BEEPS ]
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
ARCHER TO HAWKINS.
GO AHEAD, SIR.
WE'RE ALL CLEAR.
UNDERSTOOD.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
I HEARD ABOUT THE ACCIDENT
YOU AND T'POL HAD IN THE LAB.
AW, IT WAS MINOR.
[ GRUNTS ]
NOTHING TO WRITE HOME ABOUT.
BUT YOU'RE SURE THIS STUFF
IS SAFE TO BRING ON BOARD?
DON'T WORRY.
IT ONLY TENDS TO BLOW UP
IN ITS LIQUID STATE.
[ RUMBLING ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ENTERPRISE TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
GO AHEAD.
SIR, WE'VE JUST PICKED UP
A SPATIAL ANOMALY
AT YOUR COORDINATES.
WE SAW IT.
IT'S ALTERED THE COURSE
OF THE ASTEROID.
YOU'RE HEADING INTO
A DENSER PART OF THE FIELD.
GRAB A SEAT, COMMANDER.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
JUST GET US
THE HELL OUT OF HERE!
[ THUDDING ]
THE STARBOARD THRUSTER'S
FAILING!
THERE'S DEBRIS
IN THE INTAKE MANIFOLD.
CAN YOU PURGE IT?
[ BEEPING ]
WE'RE CLEAR.
BUT WE'VE ONLY GOT
ONE THRUSTER LEFT.
CAN YOU GET US HOME?
I THINK SO.
SHUTTLEPOD 2 TO ENTERPRISE.
GO AHEAD, COMMANDER.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY BACK,
BUT WE'VE TAKEN DAMAGE.
ALERT THE LAUNCH BAY CREW TO
GET READY FOR A ROUGH DOCKING.
UNDERSTOOD.
SECURE THE DOOR.
THE TRANSCEIVER'S BEEN DAMAGED.
ANY CHANCE OF REPAIRING IT?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
-T'POL?
-WHAT?
ANY CHANCE OF REPAIRING IT?
THERE'S AN AUXILIARY
TRANSMITTER.
IF I CAN GET ACCESS TO IT,
WE MAY BE ABLE
TO CONTACT ENTERPRISE.
SIR, I'VE ENCRYPTED
THE LOCKING CODES.
BUT IF THEY'RE DETERMINED
TO GET IN...
LOOKS LIKE THE IMPULSE ASSEMBLY
TOOK A BEATING.
OPEN UP THE ENGINE HOUSINGS
AND RUN A DIAGNOSTIC.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-BRIDGE TO COMMANDER TUCKER.
TUCKER HERE.
WE'RE RECEIVING A TRANSMISSION
FROM THE CAPTAIN.
IT SOUNDS URGENT.
ROUTE IT DOWN HERE.
GO AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
TRIP, WE'RE GOING TO NEED SOME
HELP GETTING OFF THIS SHIP.
HOW FAST CAN YOU BE HERE?
POD 2 TOOK SOME DAMAGE
IN THE ASTEROID FIELD, SIR.
WE'RE LOOKING AT...
A COUPLE HOURS BEFORE
WE CAN LAUNCH AGAIN.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
IT'S THE VULCAN CREW.
SOMETHING'S WRONG WITH THEM.
WE'RE GOING TO TRANSMIT
SOME BIODATA.
TELL PHLOX
TO START ANALYZING IT.
SEE IF THERE'S ANYTHING
WE CAN DO TO HELP THESE PEOPLE.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
ANYTHING ELSE?
JUST GET THAT SHUTTLE FLYING.
AYE, SIR.
ARCHER OUT.
YOU HEARD THE CAPTAIN.
GET A REPAIR TEAM DOWN HERE.
THE BULKHEAD CONTROLS
WERE SEVERED ON DECK 9.
I'VE REROUTED THEM
THROUGH THE AUXILIARY GRID.
MR. REED, ARE YOU FINISHED
WITH THOSE ACTUATOR CIRCUITS?
THEY'VE ALL BEEN REALIGNED.
-[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
-[ GRUNTS ]
YOU OKAY?
WHAT DID YOU DO?
I-I REALIGNED THE CIRCUITS,
JUST LIKE YOU ASKED ME.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
THESE AREN'T
SEQUENCED CORRECTLY!
YOU OVERLOADED
THE LOCKING MECHANISM!
THEN WE'LL HAVE TO
TRY SOMETHING ELSE.
IT'S POINTLESS.
THE CIRCUITS ARE DAMAGED!
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
I SHOULD HAVE BEEN WATCHING HIM!
YOU DIDN'T WANT ME TO SEE.
NOW I KNOW WHAT YOU WERE DOING
IN THE COMMAND CENTER.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THE XINDI STAR CHARTS.
YOU WERE ANALYZING THEM
BEHIND MY BACK,
UNDERMINING MY WORK.
NO ONE'S TRYING
TO SABOTAGE YOUR WORK.
WE SHOULD ALL JUST FOCUS ON
GETTING OFF THIS SHIP SAFELY.
THERE MIGHT BE ANOTHER WAY, SIR.
IF WE OVERLOAD THE POWER GRID,
IT WOULD DISRUPT THE SYSTEMS
ALL OVER THE SHIP,
INCLUDING
THE BULKHEAD MECHANISMS.
THE WARP REACTOR
IS UNSTABLE AS IT IS.
DISRUPTING MAIN POWER COULD SHUT
DOWN THE ANTIMATTER CONTAINMENT.
YOU'D CAUSE A REACTOR BREACH.
I DON'T THINK
WE HAVE MUCH OF A CHOICE.
YOU WANT TO KILL ALL OF US.
YOU DON'T TRUST VULCANS.
YOU NEVER HAVE.
SIR, THAT PISTOL'S SET TO KILL.
GIVE ME THE WEAPON.
DON'T THINK I'VE FORGOTTEN.
YOU BLAMED US
FOR HOLDING YOU BACK,
FOR UNDERMINING
YOUR FATHER'S WORK.
NOW YOU DECIDED TO TAKE REVENGE.
I'LL FIRE!
LISTEN TO ME.
THIS IS A RESCUE MISSION.
WE'RE HERE TO SAVE THESE PEOPLE.
YOU'RE LYING.
YOU WANT TO KILL THEM.
IF THAT'S TRUE...
THEN WHY WOULD I KEEP
OUR WEAPONS ON STUN?
IT'S NOT LOGICAL.
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ BANGING CONTINUES ]
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
T'POL AND I HAVE BEEN WORKING
WITH TRELLIUM FOR WEEKS.
SHE HASN'T SHOWN ANY SYMPTOMS.
I DON'T IMAGINE SHE WOULD HAVE.
DESPITE YOUR BEST EFFORTS, YOU
WEREN'T ABLE TO SYNTHESIZE IT
IN ANY SIGNIFICANT QUANTITIES.
THE CREW OF THE SELEYA, HOWEVER,
HAD THE MISFORTUNE
OF WANDERING INTO AN ASTEROID
FIELD FILLED WITH THE COMPOUND.
TRELLIUM-D
IS A POTENT NEUROTOXIN
TO THE VULCAN NERVOUS SYSTEM.
IT DISRUPTS
THE SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS
THAT ALLOW THEM
TO CONTROL EMOTIONS.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE RATE OF DECAY
IS ACCELERATING.
IS IT TOO LATE?
I CAN TREAT HER, BUT I NEED TO
BEGIN SYNAPTIC REGENERATION
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
WHAT ABOUT THE VULCAN CREW?
[ STATIC BUZZING ]
PHLOX, DO YOU READ ME?
I'M AFRAID THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO FOR THE OTHERS.
THEY'VE BEEN EXPOSED
FOR TOO LONG.
THE NEUROLOGICAL DAMAGE
IS IRREVERSIBLE.
THEY'RE DYING, CAPTAIN.
HE'S LYING!
HE WANTS THEM ALL TO DIE.
DOCTOR, THERE ARE
OVER 140 PEOPLE ON THIS SHIP.
I'M SORRY, BUT THEY'VE BEEN...
[ STATIC BUZZING ]
ENTERPRISE.
PHLOX, DO YOU HEAR ME?
RESPOND.
THEY'VE SHUT
THE COM SYSTEM DOWN.
CAPTAIN, THEY'RE FLOODING THE
COMPARTMENT WITH HEXAFLUORINE.
[ GASPS ]
[ ALL COUGHING ]
SHUT IT OFF.
I CAN'T. THEY'VE BYPASSED
THE ENVIRONMENTAL CONTROLS.
THEY WON'T LET YOU
DESTROY THIS SHIP.
AFTER YOU INITIATE THE OVERLOAD,
HOW LONG DO WE HAVE?
[ COUGHING ]
15 MINUTES, MAYBE LESS.
NO!
YOU HEARD WHAT THE DOCTOR SAID.
THEY CAN'T BE SAVED,
BUT YOU CAN.
MURDERER!
HELP ME GET HER OUT OF HERE.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ COUGHING ]
MALCOLM?
JUST ABOUT THERE.
COME ON.
[ COUGHING ]
CLIMB!
MALCOLM!
[ BEEPING ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME!
NO! NO!
NO!
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE!
ANOTHER 20 METERS.
CAPTAIN!
HOW WERE YOU AT THE LONG JUMP?
WATCH HER.
REED.
[ GRUNTS ]
AAH!
COME ON.
YOU CAN MAKE IT.
GET AWAY FROM ME.
IT'S OKAY.
I'LL HELP YOU.
YOU TOUCH ME, AND I'LL KILL YOU!
AAH!
[ LASER FIRE ]
[ GRUNTING ]
GO!
I SAID GO!
GIVE ME A HAND!
[ GRUNTING ]
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
I CAN'T RELEASE
THE DOCKING CLAMPS.
FULL POWER TO THRUSTERS.
-[ BEEPING ]
-WE'RE BEING HAILED.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN?
THE DOCKING CLAMPS ARE JAMMED.
WE COULD USE A HAND.
STAND BY.
YOU'RE CLEAR, SIR.
THE SHIP'S ABOUT TO BLOW.
GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE!
[ RUMBLING ]
ARCHER TO SHUTTLEPOD 2.
ARE YOU STILL IN ONE PIECE?
WE'RE FINE, SIR.
SEE YOU BACK ON ENTERPRISE.
[ SIGHS ]
WE'VE GOT OVER 60 KILOS.
IT SHOULD BE ENOUGH
TO LINE THE FORWARD HULL.
MAY BE A WHILE BEFORE PHLOX
FINDS A WAY TO INOCULATE T'POL.
TAKE THIS TO CARGO BAY ONE,
STORE IT IN A BIOHAZARD LOCKER.
AYE, SIR.
HOW'D IT GO?
YOU GOT HER OUT IN TIME,
CAPTAIN.
HER SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS
ARE MENDING NICELY.
BUT IT WILL BE A FEW DAYS
BEFORE SHE FULLY REGAINS
CONTROL OF HER EMOTIONS.
I'D LIKE TO TALK WITH HER.
[ HISSES ]
[ EXHALES ]
PHLOX WAS ABLE TO HELP YOU.
YOU'RE GONNA BE OKAY.
THE SELEYA?
IT WAS DESTROYED.
I'M SORRY,
BUT I DIDN'T HAVE A CHOICE.
THEY WERE BEYOND HELP.
THEIR FATE WAS SEALED
LONG BEFORE WE ARRIVED.
PLEASE DON'T BE LONG.
WAS COMMANDER TUCKER SUCCESSFUL?
YES AND NO.
HE COLLECTED
A GOOD SUPPLY OF TRELLIUM.
BUT IT TURNS OUT IT WAS TRELLIUM
THAT POISONED THE VULCAN CREW.
AND YOU.
IT'S ESSENTIAL
YOU PROTECT THIS SHIP.
LEAVE ME ON THE NEXT
HABITABLE PLANET.
I'M NOT GOING TO DO THAT.
YOU CAN'T ALLOW YOUR CONCERN
FOR A SINGLE CREWMAN
TO AFFECT YOUR MISSION.
THIS EXPANSE DESTROYED
EVERYONE ABOARD THE SELEYA.
DON'T LET IT HAPPEN
TO ENTERPRISE.
WE'LL FIND A WAY THROUGH THIS.
BUT I WON'T LEAVE ANYONE BEHIND,
NOT IF I CAN HELP IT.
I CAN'T TRY TO SAVE HUMANITY
WITHOUT HOLDING ON
TO WHAT MAKES ME HUMAN.
DEAD END --
AS FAR WEST AS SHE GOES.
SOMETHING TELLS ME
WE HAVEN'T SEEN THE LAST
OF THE DETECTIVE IN THE BOW TIE.
NO, HE DIED IN A HOUSE FIRE.
AH, DID HE? HMM?
THE AUTOPSY WAS INCONCLUSIVE.
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED
IF THE BODY BELONGED
TO THE DELIVERY MAN.
HMM?
WITH THE STRANGE LIMP.
YOU NEVER DID SEE HIM
LEAVE THE HOUSE.
WHAT ABOUT THE GARDENER?
HE WAS THERE, TOO.
TOO TALL.
EVEN THE PRIMITIVE FORENSICS
OF THE MID-20TH CENTURY
WOULD HAVE DETERMINED THAT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
PERHAPS WE SHOULD WATCH
AND FIND OUT.
PART OF THE FUN OF A MYSTERY
IS TRYING TO SOLVE IT
BEFORE IT ENDS, USING LOGIC.
YOU OF ALL PEOPLE
SHOULD APPRECIATE THAT.
THEN USE LOGIC MORE QUIETLY.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ALL HANDS REPORT TO STATIONS.
TACTICAL ALERT.
[ CHATTERING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
T'POL! T'POL! T'POL!
T'POL!
-T'POL!
-[ GASPS ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE ON ENTERPRISE.
YOU'RE SAFE.