( water running )
( water stops )
MAN: Hoshi.
Hello?
MAN: Do you understand me?
I think you do.
Can you see me?
Ensign Sato to Security.
MAN: Go ahead.
Hoshi?
Is everything all right?
ARCHER: I thought I was the only one
who lived here during my off hours.
I'd like you to see this.
( beeping )
These are the locations
where we've encountered spatial anomalies.
I analyzed the sensor logs
from the Xindi database.
These are the coordinates
where that vessel was affected.
Seems pretty random.
That's what I thought...
Until I ran a vector analysis
of the gravimetric waves
coming from the sphere we discovered.
The interference patterns
implied another wave source.
A second sphere?
It appears so.
The simulation suggests
that the anomalies occur
where the waves intersect.
If you're right, then we should
be able to start predicting
where we're going to run into trouble.
If we're going to create an accurate map,
we'll need precise measurements
of the sphere's gravimetric fields.
Assuming there is a second sphere,
how far away is it?
Less than four light-years.
Set a course.
Nothing?
MALCOLM: I ran every scan in the book.
There's no sign of any intruder
anywhere on the ship.
Maybe our sensors missed something.
I went through all the logs
for the past 24 hours.
To say they were uneventful
would be an understatement.
This is good news.
That I'm imagining things?
Well, you're a little on edge.
It's not uncommon to see the enemy
out of the corner of your eye.
I thought that was called paranoia.
Whatever it is, it's not uncommon.
Just the other night,
I thought I heard clicking sounds
in my quarters.
For a moment, I could have sworn
there was a Xindi-insectoid
lurking in the shadows.
What I saw wasn't a shadow.
All right. I'll keep an eye out.
( footsteps receding )
There's a mild vasodilation
in the prefrontal cortex.
That would account for your headaches.
Other than that, you're in perfect health.
Are there any more tests that you can run?
What do you expect me to find?
The last few days,
I've had the strangest feeling
that I'm being watched.
I've heard whispering down corridors,
in my quarters.
Could I have been exposed to something
that's making me hallucinate?
There's no evidence
of any mind-altering substances on board.
So basically, this is all in my head.
It appears to be.
Great.
I suppose you believe
you're dealing badly with stress.
It's not a good sign when you start
to see things that aren't there.
( chuckles )
Well, that's a matter of opinion.
On Denobula, when a person
under stress hallucinates,
it's considered healthy...
a harmless way for the subconscious
to release nervous energy.
I've always envied those
who had that facility.
I tend to keep too much bottled up inside.
I should get going.
T'Pol's asked me to translate
a section of the Xindi database.
( beeping )
MAN: Hoshi.
( static crackling )
( whispering )
That's where I'm waiting for you.
( beeps )
Ensign Sato to Lieutenant Reed.
I need help in the command center.
MAN: Hoshi.
Who are you?
Don't be frightened.
( static crackles )
Hoshi.
( echoing ) How did you get on board?
I'm nowhere near your ship.
What do you want?
You're searching for something.
I can help.
( gasps )
( grunts )
Hoshi... Are you all right?
I'm not picking up
anything out of the ordinary.
We still haven't found any ships nearby
or any uninvited guests on board.
I'm not imagining it, Captain.
You have to admit it's a possibility.
With respect, sir,
I know that my mind
can be overactive sometimes,
but that is not what's happening.
This is real.
I want you to keep Hoshi under observation
until we can sort this out.
Post a security detail outside.
And assign teams to engineering
and the armory until further notice.
Are you expecting an attack, sir?
Around here, you never know.
I'll see you both in the morning.
( sighs ) Isn't it about feeding time?
I'll take care of it
after I get you settled.
Would you mind? I'm really not that tired.
Be my guest.
The Vulcan root leaf's in that container.
That's strange.
It's...
When the alien communicates
with me, it's...
It's almost like he's inside my head,
looking at things through my eyes,
experiencing what I'm experiencing.
And talking to him is...
is like talking to myself.
Does that make any sense?
It makes perfect sense.
Listening to your thoughts
has been very pleasurable.
What?
I've been with you for several days...
studying your mind, your memories,
learning so many things about you.
Why me?
My telepathy only works in rare instances.
It takes a unique mind to process it.
Yours is the first I've found
in many years.
What do you want?
I'm only three light-years away.
My home is what you're seeing right now.
All I want is to meet you.
I don't think that'll be possible.
I know you're on an urgent mission.
That's what I want to talk to you about.
What did he tell you about the Xindi?
He's saving that for my visit.
He could have given you something
as a show of good faith.
This could be another attempt by the Xindi
to infiltrate Enterprise.
I think he wants to help.
He was horrified that
seven million of us were killed.
He says he's willing to use his abilities
to help us find the Xindi.
I think that's reason enough
to meet with him.
( beeps )
Archer to Mayweather.
MAYWEATHER: Go ahead, sir.
We're taking a slight detour.
( wind rushing )
( doors creak shut )
( doors creak )
MAN: I asked Hoshi to come alone.
The Captain's always a part
of first contact missions...
Starfleet regulations.
I hope that's not a problem.
Not at all, Captain.
I'm pleased all three of you could come.
My name is Tarquin.
I'm obviously not what you expected.
I didn't want to frighten you,
so I created a human image
when I contacted you on Enterprise.
Thank you for coming to me.
You said you could help us
with our mission.
You're searching for a weapon
that could annihilate your planet.
I may be able to find it.
But I'll need an object
that's associated with the Xindi.
Why?
Every artifact retains an imprint
of the people who made it, who used it.
I have the ability to sense
those imprints.
I could arrange
to have something sent down.
How much time would you need with it?
No more than a few days.
We didn't pick up any other bio-signs.
I take it you live here alone.
Alone.
It's an awfully big planet for one person.
I've lived here for a very long time,
Mr. Reed.
My only contact with the outside world
has been through telepathy.
Bring me the artifact.
I'd like to get started.
We'll be back as soon as we can.
Captain... One small request.
I'd like Hoshi to stay with me
while I'm working.
I'm afraid that's not appropriate.
Nonetheless,
it's a condition of my helping you.
If I'm comfortable with this...
I don't get the sense
that he would harm me.
My instincts tell me otherwise.
He's hiding something.
If he's insistent,
we could put off looking for the sphere,
stay in orbit.
It's only for a few days.
We don't have the luxury
of dealing with one problem
at a time anymore, sir.
If he can tell us something
about the Xindi weapon,
it's worth the risk.
I can take care of myself, Captain.
This is from the weapon
that attacked your planet.
We think it was a prototype...
from a much larger weapon.
This will be very useful.
May I?
Thanks.
I need a minute.
( breathes deeply ) Take your time.
Do I have to tell you
to stay on your toes?
-( door closes )
-I think that falls
under the "goes without saying"
category, sir.
Did you bring a phase-pistol?
I'll keep it under my pillow.
You know how to reach me.
( footsteps receding )
Do you always eat like this?
Only when I have company.
Thank you.
I thought you might enjoy
something familiar.
( lid clatters )
Programming these dishes was a challenge.
I had to re-create their tastes
and textures from your memory.
Please.
It should approximate
the recipe from Fiorella's
on Fountain Street in San Francisco.
You have certainly done your homework.
I've enjoyed it.
Mmm, what's this?
Dessert.
It's a delicacy from the Arakon system.
I think you'll like it.
You know,
my stomach is a little unsettled.
You told your grandmother that
every time she tried
to serve you soba noodles.
Now it's one of your favorite foods.
Since you seem to know
so much about my past,
I think it's only fair that
I know a little about yours.
Where are you from?
My homeworld
is 30 light-years from here...
a wonderful place to live,
provided you're not born telepathic.
( scoffs ) The odds are 1 in 50 million.
I was among the unlucky few.
We're considered a threat
to the rest of the population.
There's only one solution
for people like me...
To live out our lives in exile.
So we're sent to places like this...
To solitude.
I think you're familiar with it.
What do you mean?
Your parents learned you were gifted,
so you spent your childhood
with private tutors,
studying languages.
You thought it was normal
to go through your days alone.
I'm sorry.
I forget you're unaware
of how much I know about you.
Are you reading my mind continuously?
Not since you've arrived.
Now that you're here with me,
I would rather get to know you
the way other humans do.
This is great, but I'm pretty tired.
Of course
( door opens )
If you need anything else,
let me know at supper tomorrow.
I'll be working most of the day.
Uh, feel free to wander.
There are a lot
of interesting things here,
but I strongly suggest
that you stay inside.
The winds can be treacherous.
I'm sure there's enough
to keep me occupied.
If you'd like, y-y-you could
spend some time looking at this.
It's written in a dead language,
over 1,000 years old.
Everything about these people,
their homeworld,
their culture, has vanished into time.
Thank you.
You don't have to feel alone.
I won't. I'll be busy with this.
That's not what I meant.
You often feel isolated,
even around other people.
You don't have to.
( door opens, closes )
-( communicator beeps )
-Archer to the bridge.
T'POL: Yes, Captain.
I assume we're getting close.
You assume correctly.
Take us out of warp. I'm on my way.
Yes, sir.
( indistinct conversations )
( beeping )
Status.
We're getting reports
of anomalies on all decks.
-( electricity crackles )
-( man screams )
( yells )
( electricity crackling )
I got you.
There are breaches
on decks "B", "C", and "E".
Emergency bulkheads are in place,
but three subsections have decompressed.
( rumbling )
We're losing structural integrity
in the forward hull.
All stop!
The anomalies are stronger here.
If there is another sphere in the region,
it's emitting a lot more
gravimetric energy than the first one.
Which means, if we continue,
there's a good chance this ship
is gonna get torn apart.
If it is there, how far?
Approximately 75,000 kilometers.
Might as well be 75,000 light-years.
-( communicator beeps )
-Bridge to Commander Tucker.
TUCKER: Go ahead.
-How are your engines holding up?
-So far, so good.
But I wouldn't recommend putting them
through a lot more of this.
How long would it take you
to insulate a shuttlepod with trellium-D?
I'd need a day to refine enough ore
and, uh, at least 12 hours
to reconfigure the hull.
Get started.
Aye, sir.
Hold our position.
You might want to steer clear
of the launch bay
for the next couple of days.
Indeed.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to disturb you.
Not at all.
Please.
( doors creaking )
Have you had a chance to look
at the book I gave you?
I'm about halfway through.
I didn't expect you
to translate it so quickly.
Aren't you supposed to know me
better than that?
( chuckles ) What did you think of it?
It's an interesting language...
reminds me of medieval Klingon.
Any progress?
A few images, impressions.
Did you know that
there are five Xindi species?
That's what we've heard.
A great deal of conflict among them.
They don't trust one another.
Do you know where
they're building the weapon?
Not yet. I'm going to need more time.
What's this?
It helps me extend
the range of my telepathy.
My family gave it to me when I was exiled.
Without it, I never would have found you.
Would you like to try?
Is that possible?
With guidance.
If you close your eyes,
you'll begin to sense light and color.
Let the images take shape,
and let the shapes become more distinct.
-Can you see them?
-I think so.
You're trying too hard to find them.
Let the images come to you.
How do you make sense of all that?
It takes practice. Try again.
Maybe later.
I should let you get back to your work.
Uh, feel free to return...
If you'd like some company.
Thanks.
( wind rushing )
I asked you to stay inside!
Is this why you didn't want me out here?
Who are they?
They're people I knew.
The last one died over a century ago.
We should go inside.
How did they die?
Very few lifespans are as long as mine.
How old are you?
I was born over 400 years ago.
Who were they?
The first one was Morianna Taal.
She was my first companion.
Like you, she had a unique mind.
And the other three?
Companions as well.
When I lost Morianna,
I-I began to search for another...
And another.
( sighs )
Sometimes, I don't know what is worse...
being alone or having to bury the people
I've come to care about.
It's been many years
since I found someone like you.
You're right. We should go back inside.
All I'm asking is that
you consider the possibility.
You know that Enterprise
is on an important mission.
I just can't abandon my duties.
It's possible that, with my help,
your mission will be over soon.
Do you really expect me
to spend the rest of my life
on a desolate world
with someone that I have known
for less than two days?
The others had similar doubts.
But over time,
they came to appreciate
what I had to offer them.
No one will ever understand you
the way I can.
I am grateful for your help,
and I'm happy to stay here while you work,
but I have no intention
of becoming your next companion.
( breathing deeply )
If you think projecting yourself as human
is going to make me change my mind,
you're mistaken.
You've let your fear of the unknown
stand in your way far too many times.
You almost left Enterprise
early in its mission
because you didn't think
you could control your fears.
But in spite of that, you stayed.
It strengthened you.
This situation is no different.
You obviously misinterpreted
a few memories,
because this situation is very different.
I'm giving you the chance
to experience something
you've searched for your entire life.
It's the reason you study languages,
to make unique connections with people.
I don't need you to help me do that.
Then why do you seem so isolated?
You live on a ship
filled with your own people,
and yet there are many times
when you feel alone.
Stay with me.
I'll teach you ways of sharing
thoughts and emotions no human can.
I already told you, I'm not interested.
You're lying, Hoshi.
I can hear everything you're thinking.
What I'm thinking
is none of your business!
Michio.
Your grandfather...
He's the last person
you were truly close to.
But he died a long time ago.
Leave me alone.
You can have
that kind of connection again.
Leave me alone!
I'm sorry.
I know this must seem overwhelming.
Think about what I've said.
You're going to have a great deal of time.
( beeping )
Sensors say we're passing through
a gravimetric distortion.
( beeping )
No anomalies.
Trellium seems to be doing its job.
-( communicator beeps )
-Archer to Enterprise.
T'POL: Go ahead.
We're approaching 79,000 kilometers.
Still no sign of the cloaking barrier.
Adjust your heading to 016 mark 2.
ARCHER: Stand by.
( rumbling )
( beeping )
That felt promising.
I believe you just grazed the perimeter.
Turn starboard, 3.6 degrees.
( beeping )
I think we've found it.
T'POL: Maintain course.
You should be heading directly
toward the cloaking barrier.
Power's fluctuating!
( beeping )
Hull integrity?
Some micro-fractures,
but nothing we can't handle.
TUCKER: Switching to backup!
( beeping )
Trip.
Let's get going with the scans.
( buzzing )
TUCKER: Ah, hell!
Is there a problem?
The sensor relays were damaged.
How much time do you need?
Not long,
but we'll have to get back to Enterprise.
I need to open up the circuit
housings on the undercarriage--
No way to get to them from the inside.
Bring the descent thrusters online.
You're not planning to land on that thing?
Thrusters, Trip,
and get the E.V. suits ready.
( grunts )
TUCKER:
Not exactly my idea of shore leave.
ARCHER: Get to work.
I'm gonna take a look around.
TUCKER: Don't get lost.
( chuckles )
ARCHER: How's it coming, Trip?
Almost there, sir. Just two more relays.
-( electricity crackles )
-( yells )
Captain!
( hissing )
What happened?
The port thruster ignited.
I can see that.
When I was bypassing the last relay,
I must have triggered a surge
in the propulsion system.
Son of a bitch!
It's going to be a long time
before Enterprise decides
to come looking for us.
Can we launch without a port thruster?
We can sure as hell try.
ARCHER: Whoever gets the first clear shot.
Careful, sir. That was awfully
close to the O2 recycler.
I need to spend more time in the armory.
( metal screeching )
( communicator beeps )
Archer to Enterprise.
We're here, Captain.
It was right where you said it was, T'Pol.
We got all the scans you asked for.
ARCHER: Captain's starlog, supplemental.
While T'Pol analyzes the data
from the sphere,
we've set a course to pick up Ensign Sato
and find out if the alien
learned anything about the Xindi.
( knocking on door )
( door opens )
May I come in? I won't be long.
I just heard from your captain.
Enterprise will be here in a few minutes.
I have learned a great deal
about the Xindi weapon.
I'm sure he'll find
the information useful.
Thank you for all your help.
Have you given any more
thought to my offer?
I can't stay here. You know that.
I understand.
I was foolish to think
it was even a possibility.
The next time you invite
someone for a visit,
you might want to let them know
that you're looking
for a lifelong companion.
I won't forget.
Uh...
Please keep the book
as a reminder of your time here.
I was hoping you'd say that.
I'm nearly done,
and I'm anxious to see how it ends.
After I've briefed Captain Archer,
I'll send him to you.
It was a privilege knowing you.
How was your stay?
I'm eager to get back to Enterprise.
I'm sure.
If it's any consolation,
your time here was well spent.
We've learned more about
the Xindi than I expected.
And he's offered to keep
supplying us with information
for as long as we're in range,
thanks to you.
Glad I could help, sir.
There is one condition.
He wants you to stay with him
while he continues his work.
I assume you told him
that wouldn't be possible.
I won't order you to do this, Hoshi,
but it may be our best chance
of finding the weapon
before it's too late.
With any luck, it'll only take
a few weeks, maybe a month.
We'd come back for you
as soon as the mission's over.
I don't need to tell you
what's at stake, Ensign.
I'll go back to my quarters
and pick up a few things.
Thank you, Hoshi.
There's no reason for you to leave.
Just give me a list of what you need,
and I'll have it sent down.
I should brief my replacement
on the U.T. upgrades.
We'll take care of it. Don't worry.
At least give me a chance
to say goodbye to the crew.
I wish there was time.
It won't take long, sir.
I might not see my friends again.
I'm sure Travis will understand.
Travis?
Travis and the others.
They realize how important this is.
I was just thinking about Travis.
You're a regular mind reader.
We've known each other a long time.
Where is Captain Archer?
We'll be back for you as soon as we can.
Where is he?
Hoshi.
-Where is Captain Archer?
-Hoshi.
Open a channel to Ensign Sato.
( beeping )
Our signal's not getting through, sir.
There's some kind of disruption field.
MALCOLM: Sir.
ARCHER: What's going on?
My station's down.
Everything's going off-line...
Main and auxiliary power,
warp engines, life support.
( electricity humming )
Nice try.
What were you planning to tell
my captain when he got back?
Were you gonna appear as me
and beg him to let you stay?
No, you can't do that, can you?
I'm the only one on board
that you can play your tricks with.
Enterprise has already returned.
Their fate is in your hands.
What is that supposed to mean?
I can't let you leave, Hoshi.
I've waited too long to find you.
What's happened to Enterprise?
If you agree to stay,
they won't be harmed.
They'll be free to leave orbit.
Let me speak to Captain Archer.
That's not possible.
Why the hell not?
You'll be happy here, I promise you.
Why can't I speak to Captain Archer?
There's no power on your vessel,
and there won't be until
you agree to remain with me.
You would kill over 80 people
to keep me here?
I don't want to kill anyone.
That's why it's essential
that you agree to stay.
You mustn't do that.
( breathing heavily )
It's very fragile.
I'm counting on that.
Now undo whatever you've done to my ship,
or you will never contact
anyone again with this thing.
An empty threat, Hoshi.
As long as you're with me,
I won't need to contact anyone else.
As long as I'm with you...
another 60, 70 years?
Then what?
What'll you do when
I'm grave number five out there?
Without this,
you will never find another companion.
You will be alone
for the rest of your life.
Please, think of what I can offer you.
This is your last chance.
( electricity humming )
ARCHER: Report.
Power's returning to all systems.
Malcolm?
Weapons are coming back online.
Tactical alert.
Aye, sir.
( beeping )
It's Ensign Sato.
Put her through.
HOSHI: Captain, are you all right?
We are now. What the hell's going on?
I think it's time to come get me.
ARCHER: Captain's starlog, supplemental.
Ensign Sato has returned to Enterprise,
but without any new information
on the Xindi.
I'm hoping T'Pol's analysis of
the second sphere will bring better news.
What have you got?
The data you collected
allowed me to create
a nearly accurate map of the anomalies.
Nearly?
These are the coordinates
where we've encountered strong anomalies.
The waves aren't intersecting
where they're supposed to.
Exactly.
The locations are being influenced
by more than two gravimetric sources.
A third sphere?
A third sphere would correct
some of the error,
but not all of it.
So I had the computer run
a covariant extrapolation.
How many?
We'll need to get farther
into the expanse to be certain, but...
At least 50.
Fifty man-made spheres,
each one the size of a small moon.
And each one generating massive
amounts of gravimetric energy.
Did it ever occur to you
that whoever built these things
may have done it to create the expanse?
Why would someone want to create
a web of crippling anomalies?
What are you doing here?
Did you enjoy the ending?
You can't do this.
I don't want you watching me.
This is the last time... I promise.
I've brought you information
to give to your captain.
Why now?
You're on a dangerous mission.
I don't want to see you harmed.
( chuckles ) Who knows?
You may change your mind about me someday.
-( door chimes )
-Come in.
I thought I told you to get some rest.
He came to my quarters.
I was afraid that might happen.
He gave me these coordinates.
-What are they for?
-A Xindi colony.
He said they're building part
of the weapon there.