[ EXPLOSIONS ]
ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I HAVE ORDERS TO KEEP YOU HERE.
ORDERS?
FROM WHO?
THE CAPTAIN.
WE'RE LOSING
FORWARD HULL PLATING.
TARGET THEIR ENGINES.
NO EFFECT.
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON?!
SOMEONE TAKE HIM
BACK TO HIS QUARTERS.
WEAPONS ARE OFF-LINE!
CAPTAIN.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ GROANS SOFTLY ]
HELLO?
YOU'RE UP EARLY.
T'POL?
I KNOW THIS
ALL SEEMS UNFAMILIAR.
I PROMISE
I'LL EXPLAIN EVERYTHING.
WHY DON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
BREAKFAST IS ALMOST READY.
WHERE ARE WE?
JONATHAN, PLEASE, SIT DOWN.
I'LL ANSWER
ALL OF YOUR QUESTIONS.
TODAY IS A VERY IMPORTANT DAY.
I HAVE A GREAT DEAL TO TELL YOU.
WHAT'S THE LAST THING
YOU REMEMBER?
I WAS IN THE COMMAND CENTER
LOOKING AT LONG-RANGE SCANS.
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER
YOU LEFT THE COMMAND CENTER?
WE WERE IN A CORRIDOR,
YOU AND I,
ON OUR WAY TO THE BRIDGE.
THIS WILL BE DIFFICULT
FOR YOU TO ACCEPT,
BUT THAT WAS 12 YEARS AGO.
YOU COMING TONIGHT?
I HADN'T PLANNED ON IT.
I CAN MAKE MOVIE NIGHT
MANDATORY FOR SENIOR OFFICERS.
YOU'LL ENJOY IT.
"ROSEMARY'S BABY."
-IT'LL SCARE THE HELL OUT OF --
-[ EXPLOSION ]
ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
REPORT.
THERE'S A POWER SURGE
IN THE STARBOARD NACELLE
IT SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN CAUSED
BY AN ANOMALY.
TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
[ BEEPING ]
THE HELM'S NOT RESPONDING.
THE STARBOARD INJECTORS
ARE FUSED.
I'M READING
MORE ANOMALIES AHEAD.
ALTER COURSE.
20 DEGREES TO PORT.
[ GROANS ]
[ MOANS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
YOU HAVE TO GET OUT OF HERE.
I'M NOT LEAVING YOU.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
LIKE A SHUTTLEPOD
LANDED ON MY HEAD.
WAS ANYONE ELSE HURT?
NO.
CAPTAIN, THERE ARE A FEW
QUESTIONS I HAVE TO ASK YOU.
WELL, IT'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
I WANT TO GET TO THE BRIDGE.
I'M AFRAID I HAVE TO INSIST.
WHEN DID YOU LAST SPEAK
TO COMMANDER TUCKER?
THIS MORNING.
STAFF BRIEFING.
WHY?
WHAT'S GOING ON, PHLOX?
THE ANOMALY IN THE CORRIDOR
LEFT SOMETHING BEHIND.
WE'VE NEVER SEEN IT BEFORE.
THIS IS A MICROCELLULAR SCAN
OF YOUR HIPPOCAMPUS.
YOU'VE BEEN INFECTED BY
SEVERAL CLUSTERS OF PARASITES.
THEY HAVEN'T CAUSED
ANY TISSUE DAMAGE,
BUT THEY'RE IMPAIRING
CERTAIN SYNAPTIC FUNCTIONS.
THEY'RE PREVENTING YOU FROM
FORMING NEW LONG-TERM MEMORIES.
LONG TERM?
YOU CAN RECALL EVENTS THAT
HAPPENED BEFORE THE INFECTION,
BUT EVERYTHING AFTER
FADES WITHIN A FEW HOURS.
CAPTAIN, YOU'VE BEEN IN SICK BAY
FOR THE PAST THREE DAYS.
YOU LAST SPOKE
TO COMMANDER TUCKER
ABOUT SEVEN HOURS AGO.
HE CAME TO SEE YOU.
RIGHT HERE.
YOU CAN'T REMOVE
THESE PARASITES?
SO FAR THEY HAVEN'T RESPONDED
TO ANY TRADITIONAL THERAPIES.
BUT I'M, UM, SYNTHESIZING AN
ANTIGEN THAT SHOWS SOME PROMISE.
YOU CAN BE ASSURED
I WON'T STOP WORKING ON THIS
UNTIL I FIND A CURE.
THE DOCTOR CONTINUED
TO SEARCH FOR A REMEDY
OVER THE NEXT SEVERAL WEEKS.
COMMANDER TUCKER AND I
DID OUR BEST
TO KEEP YOU UPDATED EACH DAY
ON THE PROGRESS OF OUR MISSION.
IT LOOKED LIKE WE HAD A LEAD
ON THAT XINDI SHIP,
THE ONE WE PLANTED
THE TRACKING DEVICE ON.
BUT IT TURNED OUT TO BE
A GARBAGE SCOW.
THEY WERE CARRYING A SHIPMENT
WITH THE SAME
RADIOLYTIC SIGNATURE.
[ SIGHS ]
I HAD AN IDEA THIS MORNING
AFTER YOU TOLD ME WHAT HAPPENED.
I CAME UP WITH A WAY TO UPGRADE
THE ANTIMATTER INDUCERS.
WE CAN TRAVEL FARTHER
ON LESS FUEL.
LET ME GUESS.
I ALREADY GAVE YOU THESE SPECS.
A WEEK AGO.
BUT YOUR UPGRADES
ARE WORKING NICELY.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
I SHOULD GET BACK
TO ENGINEERING.
SEE YOU BOTH LATER.
I IMAGINE
THAT MUST HAPPEN OFTEN.
MAYBE THESE DAILY BRIEFINGS
AREN'T SUCH A GOOD IDEA.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S JUST
A WASTE OF YOUR TIME.
AND TRIP'S.
I DISAGREE.
WE BOTH RELY ON YOUR EXPERIENCE.
YOU CAN STILL CONTRIBUTE
TO THE SUCCESS OF THIS MISSION.
I'M SURE YOU HAVE WORK TO DO.
I'LL BE IN MY QUARTERS.
IN THE CORRIDOR,
WHEN THE ANOMALY HIT,
I URGED YOU TO LEAVE ME BEHIND.
IF YOU HAD,
IT'S LIKELY I'D BE THE ONE
SUFFERING FROM THIS CONDITION.
FORTUNATELY,
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU.
CAPTAIN.
I NEVER EXPRESSED MY GRATITUDE
FOR WHAT YOU DID.
I SUPPOSE THERE'S NOT MUCH POINT
IN THANKING ME.
A FEW HOURS FROM NOW,
I WON'T REMEMBER IT.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
-[ BEEPS ]
-BRIDGE TO T'POL.
GO AHEAD.
WE'RE RECEIVING A HAIL
THROUGH THE SUBSPACE BUOY.
IT'S STARFLEET.
I'M ON MY WAY.
THIS WAS NOT A CONVERSATION
I WAS LOOKING FORWARD TO.
IT WAS ADMIRAL FORREST.
THE COMMAND COUNCIL
HAD REVIEWED THE DOCTOR'S REPORT
ON YOUR CONDITION.
THEY RELIEVED YOU OF DUTY AND
GRANTED ME A FIELD COMMISSION.
FORREST MADE YOU CAPTAIN.
I SUPPOSE CONGRATULATIONS
ARE IN ORDER,
EVEN IF THEY ARE BELATED.
I GUESS...
...THESE PARASITES WEREN'T
SO EASY TO REMOVE AFTER ALL.
PHLOX DISCOVERED
THAT THE ORGANISMS
ARE FROM A DOMAIN
OUTSIDE NORMAL SPACE-TIME.
THEY EXIST IN A STATE
OF INTERSPATIAL FLUX.
NONE OF HIS TREATMENTS
HAD ANY EFFECT ON THEM.
WHAT ABOUT THE MISSION?
DID YOU FIND THE XINDI WEAPON?
AFTER SEVERAL MONTHS
OF SEARCHING,
WE LEARNED WHERE THE WEAPON
WAS BEING CONSTRUCTED.
BUT THE XINDI KNEW
WE WERE GETTING CLOSE.
THEY DISPATCHED TWO VESSELS
TO INTERCEPT US.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
THAT LAST ONE
TOOK OUT WARP ENGINES.
THEY'RE LOCKING ON
TO THE STARBOARD DOCKING PORT.
SEND SECURITY TEAMS.
I'M READING 23 INTRUDERS
ON DECKS "C," "D," AND "E."
HAVE YOUR MEN SET UP A DEFENSE
PERIMETER ON "B" DECK.
[ GROANING ]
WE'VE LOST WEAPONS.
IS THEIR SHIP
STILL DOCKED WITH US?
IT IS.
BOTH SHIPS ARE DISABLED.
WE'VE LOST 13 OF THE CREW.
22 INJURED.
SEVERAL CRITICAL.
THE XINDI?
WE'VE TAKEN NINE PRISONERS.
BUT THE BRIG
WAS ONLY DESIGNED FOR TWO.
I'M NOT SURE
WHAT TO DO WITH THE OTHERS.
BLOW THEM OUT THE AIRLOCK.
PUT THEM IN CREW QUARTERS
UNDER HEAVY GUARD.
HOW ARE THE REPAIRS COMING?
WE SHOULD HAVE HULL PLATING
AND TORPEDOES
IN THE NEXT COUPLE OF HOURS.
THE WARP DRIVE'S
ANOTHER QUESTION.
THE STARBOARD NACELLE'S
A LOST CAUSE.
HALF THE COILS HAVE BEEN FUSED.
HOW LONG TO REPAIR THEM?
IF WE WERE AT JUPITER STATION,
THREE WEEKS.
OUT HERE, I'D HAVE TO REBUILD
THE COIL ASSEMBLY FROM SCRATCH.
SIX MONTHS MINIMUM.
FOR NOW THE BEST
I CAN GIVE YOU IS WARP 1.7.
WE'RE NOT GONNA GET VERY FAR
AT THAT SPEED.
RESUME OUR PREVIOUS HEADING.
DISMISSED.
HOW CAN WE KEEP GOING
WITH ONE WARP ENGINE?
THERE'S NO OTHER OPTION.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
WERE YOU THINKING
WHEN YOU RAMMED THAT SHIP?
I CHOSE THE LOGICAL COURSE
OF ACTION.
SINCE THE CAPTAIN GOT SICK,
THIS MISSION'S TAKEN
ONE WRONG TURN AFTER ANOTHER.
IF YOU BELIEVE
I'VE ACTED IMPROPERLY,
I SUGGEST YOU CONTACT
ADMIRAL FORREST.
YOU SAID WE EVENTUALLY
FOUND THE WEAPON.
HOW COULD WE MANAGE THAT
WITHOUT WARP ENGINES?
WE LOCATED THE FACILITY WHERE
THE XINDI CONSTRUCTED THE PROBE.
BUT IT HAD
ALREADY BEEN DEPLOYED.
EARTH?
DESTROYED.
THEY DIDN'T STOP
AT YOUR HOMEWORLD.
THEY ATTACKED EVERY
HUMAN OUTPOST THEY COULD FIND.
MARS.
ALPHA CENTAURI.
VEGA COLONY.
ALL WERE DESTROYED.
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
HOW MANY OF US ARE LEFT?
LESS THAN 6,000.
NO.
WE'RE ON THE FIFTH PLANET
IN THE CETI ALPHA SYSTEM.
IT'S FAR FROM THE EXPANSE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE CREW?
MOST OF THEM
ARE STILL ABOARD THE SHIP.
IT'S IN ORBIT,
PATROLLING THIS SYSTEM.
HOW DID...
...ALL THESE PEOPLE GET HERE?
SURVIVORS
FROM HUMAN COLONIES REALIZED
THEY NEEDED A PLACE
TO TAKE REFUGE.
SEVERAL CONVOYS
HEADED FOR THIS SYSTEM.
ONE OF THEM WAS LED
BY ENTERPRISE.
[ BEEPING ]
THERE'S A SHIP APPROACHING
AT HIGH WARP.
IT'S VULCAN.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY'RE HAILING US.
AMBASSADOR.
I NEED TO SPEAK WITH YOU,
T'POL.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
THAT UNIFORM
DOESN'T SUIT YOU, CAPTAIN.
I DOUBT YOU TRAVELED ALL THIS
WAY TO CRITICIZE MY ATTIRE.
I WANT YOU TO RETURN WITH ME
TO VULCAN.
I'M NO LONGER
UNDER YOUR AUTHORITY.
IT'S NOT AN ORDER.
IT'S A REQUEST.
FOR YOUR OWN SAFETY.
TWO WEEKS AGO THE HIGH COMMAND
RECEIVED A DISTRESS CALL
FROM THE EARTH CONVOY
IN THE MUTARA SYSTEM.
BY THE TIME
OUR SHIPS REACHED THEM,
THEY FOUND NOTHING
BUT A FIELD OF DEBRIS.
THE WEAPON SIGNATURES
WERE XINDI.
EVEN IF YOUR SHIPS DO MANAGE
TO REACH CETI ALPHA,
IT'S MOST LIKELY YOU'LL FIND
AN ARMADA WAITING FOR YOU.
WE'RE PREPARED TO CONFRONT THEM.
IT WAS A MISTAKE ORDERING YOU
TO LEAVE ENTERPRISE.
IT FORCED YOU TO MAKE
AN IMPULSIVE DECISION.
IF YOU RETURN WITH ME NOW,
THE HIGH COMMAND IS PREPARED
TO REINSTATE YOUR RANK.
I WON'T LEAVE THEM.
THEM OR HIM?
THERE ARE SPECIALISTS ON VULCAN
THAT CAN HELP ARCHER.
YOU'D TAKE HIM AS WELL?
IF YOU RETURN TO VULCAN.
YOU OWE THE HUMANS NOTHING.
THEY CHOSE TO LEAVE EARTH
BEFORE THEY WERE READY.
IF THEY'D ACCEPTED OUR COUNSEL,
THIS TRAGEDY
WOULD HAVE BEEN AVOIDED.
WE COULD HAVE SAVED THEM.
HOW?
WE HELD BACK THEIR WARP PROGRAM
FOR 100 YEARS.
A POLICY WHICH YOU SUPPORTED.
IF WE WOULD HAVE HELPED THEM
DEVELOP FASTER SHIPS,
BETTER DEFENSES...
YOUR EMOTIONAL ATTACHMENT TO
ARCHER IS CLOUDING YOUR LOGIC.
WE'LL BE WITHIN RANGE
FOR ANOTHER 30 HOURS,
SHOULD YOU RECONSIDER.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
DID THINGS GO WELL
WITH THE VULCANS?
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THAT THEY WERE --
THERE WAS OBVIOUSLY A REASON
I CHOSE THESE QUARTERS.
YOU CAN SEE A LOT
FROM THIS WINDOW.
WHAT DID THEY WANT?
THEY WERE HERE
TO REPLENISH OUR SUPPLIES.
HUH.
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
EVERYTHING YOU TOLD ME.
I REALIZE I'M NOT FIT
TO COMMAND THE SHIP,
BUT THERE'S GOT TO BE
SOME WAY I CAN HELP.
I COULD GIVE TRIP A HAND
IN ENGINEERING.
WE TRIED SOMETHING SIMILAR
TO THAT A FEW MONTHS AGO.
IT WAS UNCOMFORTABLE FOR YOU.
SO I'M SUPPOSED TO STAY LOCKED
UP IN MY QUARTERS ALL DAY?
YOU OFTEN TAKE PORTHOS
FOR A WALK,
VISIT THE CLASSROOMS
ON "D" DECK.
THE CHILDREN ENJOY HEARING
ABOUT OUR EARLIER MISSIONS.
IN OTHER WORDS...
...JUST STAY OUT OF THE WAY.
AFTER NEARLY A YEAR,
WE ARRIVED IN THIS SYSTEM.
OUR CONVOY WAS THE ONLY ONE
TO REACH IT.
THE OTHERS HAD ALL BEEN
ATTACKED AND DESTROYED.
THIS PLANET'S
BARELY MINSHARA CLASS.
MAYBE WE SHOULD'VE PICKED ONE
WITH A LITTLE MORE
BLUE AND GREEN ON IT.
I'D LIKE TO HEAD DOWN
WITH A SURVEY TEAM
AND START SCOUTING
FOR COLONY SITES.
YOU'RE NEEDED ON ENTERPRISE.
THE CIVILIAN LEADERS ARE
GOING TO WANT TO MEET WITH YOU.
ME?
YOU'RE THE ONE TO DEAL WITH.
I'M RESIGNING MY COMMISSION.
YOU SURE YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
CAPTAIN ARCHER WILL BE
BETTER OFF ON THE SURFACE
WITH THE OTHERS.
HE'LL NEED A CARETAKER,
SOMEONE HE TRUSTS.
I CAN'T BE IN TWO PLACES
AT THE SAME TIME.
YOU'RE MAKING
ONE HELL OF A SACRIFICE.
WHY?
I HAVE MY REASONS.
THE CIVILIAN SHIPS
WERE DISASSEMBLED
FOR THEIR COMPONENTS
AND RAW MATERIALS.
WE USED THEM
TO CONSTRUCT THE SETTLEMENT.
AT THIS POINT, YOU OFTEN WONDER
IF YOU'RE THE VICTIM
OF SOME ELABORATE DECEPTION.
THE THOUGHT DID CROSS MY MIND.
MARGARET MULLIN.
YOU MET HER
WHEN YOU WERE 24 YEARS OLD,
DURING FLIGHT SCHOOL
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE NIGHT BEFORE YOU GRADUATED,
YOU ASKED HER TO MARRY YOU
OUTSIDE OF HER APARTMENT
ON WESTGATE AVENUE.
SHE TURNED YOU DOWN.
SHE SAID SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO BECOME A STARFLEET WIDOW.
HOW THE HELL DID YOU KNOW THAT?
OUR RELATIONSHIP HAS EVOLVED
OVER THE YEARS.
EXACTLY HOW FAR HAS IT EVOLVED?
NOTHING SEEMS TO HAVE CHANGED
SINCE YOUR LAST EXAM.
IS THIS WHY YOU CAME
ALL THE WAY FROM DENOBULA?
TO GIVE ME A CHECKUP?
YOU DIDN'T TELL HIM?
AFTER THE SETTLEMENT
WAS ESTABLISHED,
IT BECAME CLEAR
THAT I WAS NEVER GOING TO FIND
A TREATMENT FOR YOUR CONDITION
IF I REMAINED HERE.
SO I RETURNED HOME
AND CONSULTED WITH SOME OF
THE FINEST NEUROSURGEONS
AND QUANTUM THEORISTS
ON DENOBULA.
MY COLLEAGUES BELIEVED
THERE WAS NO WAY
TO DESTROY THESE PARASITES,
SHORT OF VAPORIZING YOU
IN A SUBSPACE IMPLOSION.
THEY ASSURED ME THE TECHNOLOGY
TO DO WHAT WAS REQUIRED
DID NOT EXIST.
AND, UH, THEY WERE CORRECT.
IT TOOK ALMOST A DECADE
TO DEVELOP.
BUT NOW I'M READY
TO PUT IT TO THE TEST.
THE PROCEDURE REQUIRES
TREMENDOUS AMOUNTS OF ENERGY
LEVELS THAT CAN ONLY BE PRODUCED
IN THE REACTOR
OF A WARP-POWERED STARSHIP.
WE'RE GOING TO ENTERPRISE.
[ BLOWS WHISTLE ]
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU, SIR.
CAPTAIN TUCKER.
I DON'T THINK YOU NEED
TO CALL ME "SIR" ANYMORE.
OLD HABITS.
I APOLOGIZE
FOR THE LOW LIGHTING.
WE'RE RUNNING ON RESERVE POWER.
ANTIMATTER'S AT A PREMIUM
THESE DAYS.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN
SINCE YOU TOOK COMMAND?
NINE YEARS.
I'VE, UH, GOT SOME PEOPLE
WHO'D LIKE TO SAY HELLO.
YOU'RE LOOKING WELL, SIR.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THANK YOU.
COMMANDER, IS IT?
ACTUALLY, I'VE JUST
BEEN PROMOTED TO CAPTAIN.
MALCOLM'S TAKING OVER
THE INTREPID FROM RAMIREZ.
DID EVERYONE GET THEIR OWN SHIP
WHILE I WAS GONE?
NOT EVERYONE, SIR.
HOSHI.
THERE'S A RECEPTION
IN THE MESS HALL.
IF YOU'RE FEELING UP TO IT.
A VISIT TO ENGINEERING
MAY BE IN ORDER FIRST.
I'LL BE USING A HIGHLY FOCUSED
ANTIPROTON BEAM
TO ERADICATE THE PARASITES.
WE'LL START
WITH THIS CLUSTER TODAY.
WHY NOT REMOVE
ALL OF THEM AT ONCE?
THIS PROCEDURE'S
NEVER BEEN ATTEMPTED BEFORE.
WE SHOULD MOVE CAUTIOUSLY.
WHEN CAN YOU BEGIN?
THE EMITTERS SHOULD BE
CALIBRATED WITHIN THE HOUR.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
YOU LEFT THE RECEPTION EARLY.
IT WAS A LITTLE DISTURBING.
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE, I SAW
MOST OF THOSE PEOPLE JUST...
A FEW HOURS AGO.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN EASY
FOR YOU.
TELLING ME THE SAME STORY
OVER AND OVER AGAIN
FOR 12 YEARS.
I DON'T ALWAYS
TELL IT IN DETAIL.
I HOPE I'VE TOLD YOU
THIS BEFORE, BUT...
...I'M VERY GRATEFUL FOR
EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE FOR ME.
IF THIS WORKS --
-[ BEEPS ]
-PHLOX TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
-GO AHEAD.
-WE'RE READY.
I'M PICKING UP AN INTERMITTENT
DURANIUM SIGNATURE.
-IS IT A SHIP?
-I'M NOT CERTAIN.
IT'S IN A CLOSE ORBIT
AROUND THE SUN.
WE'D BETTER CHECK IT OUT.
LAY IN A COURSE.
INCREASE TO 800 MILLICOCHRANES.
INCREASE TO 850.
THERE'S A SMALL VESSEL
JUST OUTSIDE THE CHROMOSPHERE.
IS IT XINDI?
THE HULL CONFIGURATION
DOESN'T MATCH.
THERE'S ONE BIO-SIGN ON BOARD.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
THIS IS CAPTAIN CHARLES TUCKER.
IS THERE SOMETHING
WE CAN HELP YOU WITH?
[ BEEPING ]
-HE'S MOVING.
-FOLLOW HIM.
HIS WARP COILS ARE CHARGING.
TARGET ONE OF HIS NACELLES.
BRING IT INTO THE LAUNCH BAY.
JUST AS
MY SIMULATIONS PREDICTED.
THERE'S NO TRACE OF
THE PARASITES I TARGETED.
WELL, I UNDERSTAND I MAY HAVE
A PASSENGER ON MY VOYAGE HOME.
I'M REMAINING AT THE SETTLEMENT
FOR THE TIME BEING.
HE MAY NEED MY HELP
DURING HIS RECOVERY.
HAVE YOU TOLD THE CAPTAIN
HOW YOU FEEL ABOUT HIM?
IT'S OBVIOUS
YOU'VE BECOME QUITE ATTACHED.
IT'S NOTHING TO BE ASHAMED OF.
VULCANS EXPERIENCE THE SAME
EMOTIONS AS ANY OTHER SPECIES.
THEY'RE SIMPLY BETTER
AT HIDING THEM.
I'M NOT HIDING ANYTHING.
HE RISKED HIS LIFE TO SAVE ME.
I'M MERELY REPAYING A DEBT.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE
WHAT IT MUST HAVE BEEN LIKE.
SPENDING ALL THOSE YEARS
IN THAT HOUSE,
LEARNING SO MUCH ABOUT HIM.
YET HE REMEMBERS
NOTHING ABOUT YOU
BEYOND THE DAY HE BECAME ILL.
IF WE ARE SUCCESSFUL, PERHAPS...
...THINGS WILL BE DIFFERENT.
THERE'S A DISCREPANCY
IN THESE SCANS.
WHAT IS IT?
I DEAL IN RIGELIAN FLAMEGEMS.
I WAS WAITING FOR A PROSPECTIVE
BUYER WHEN YOU ATTACKED ME.
YOU PICKED AN ODD PLACE
FOR A BUSINESS TRANSACTION.
WE SEARCHED YOUR SHIP.
WE DIDN'T FIND ANY CARGO.
THAT'S BECAUSE
I JETTISONED IT ALL.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GOING TO ARREST ME.
FLAMEGEMS ARE ILLEGAL
IN THIS REGION.
WE FOUND YOUR SPECIES
IN OUR VULCAN DATABASE.
IT APPEARS YRIDIANS
ARE INFORMATION DEALERS.
WHO HIRED YOU?
WAS IT THE XINDI?
XINDI?
MAYBE WE DIDN'T GIVE HIS VESSEL
A CLOSE ENOUGH LOOK.
GO BACK TO THE LAUNCH BAY.
USE A PLASMA TORCH
AND SLICE THAT SHIP
INTO NEAT LITTLE PIECES.
KEEP AT IT UNTIL YOU FIND
SOME EVIDENCE
THAT SUPPORTS HIS STORY.
YOU'RE GOING TO DESTROY MY SHIP?
IT'S NOT YOU THEY WANT.
IT'S THE DENOBULAN.
PHLOX?
I WAS HIRED TO FOLLOW HIM.
HIRED BY WHO?!
I DON'T KNOW!
THEY WORK THROUGH
INTERMEDIARIES.
I WAS PAID
TO FOLLOW THE DENOBULAN
IF HE EVER LEFT HIS HOMEWORLD.
WHAT DID YOU TELL THEM?!
ANSWER ME!
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
YOUR ENGINEERS
WON'T LET US CONTINUE
WITH THE CAPTAIN'S TREATMENT.
THOSE WERE MY ORDERS.
LOOK, I'D DO ANYTHING
TO HELP THE CAPTAIN,
BUT WE'VE GOT BIGGER PROBLEMS
AT THE MOMENT.
THIS MAY BE THE ONLY SOLUTION
TO YOUR PROBLEMS, CAPTAIN.
DESTROYING THESE PARASITES
IS MOST LIKELY THE KEY
TO SAVING HUMANITY AND EARTH.
EARTH'S GONE.
THIS IMAGE WAS TAKEN
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
YOU CAN SEE THE REGION
WHERE I ERADICATED
THE FIRST CLUSTER OF PARASITES.
IT'S GONE IN THIS IMAGE AS WELL.
-DOC --
-THIS SCAN WAS TAKEN
OVER 12 YEARS AGO.
THE CLUSTER HAS DISAPPEARED
FROM ALL THE SCANS I'VE TAKEN
OVER THE LAST 12 YEARS.
IT'S AS THOUGH
IT NEVER EXISTED AT ALL.
BY DESTROYING THE ORGANISMS
IN THE PRESENT,
WE APPEAR TO HAVE
NEUTRALIZED THEM IN THE PAST.
WE KNOW THEY'RE FROM
ANOTHER SPATIAL DOMAIN.
APPARENTLY, THEY ALSO EXIST
OUTSIDE OF TIME.
IF WE CAN ELIMINATE
ALL THE PARASITES,
IT'S POSSIBLE
THE CAPTAIN'S INFECTION
WILL NEVER HAVE OCCURRED.
HISTORY MAY BE ALTERED.
CAPTAIN ARCHER
WILL HAVE REMAINED
IN COMMAND OF ENTERPRISE.
OUR MISSION IN THE EXPANSE
COULD HAVE
AN ENTIRELY DIFFERENT OUTCOME.
WE ONLY HAVE TO DIVERT POWER
FOR A FEW HOURS.
I AM CERTAIN I CAN COMPLETE
THE PROCEDURE IN THAT TIME.
I'M SORRY.
WE NEED ALL THE POWER WE'VE GOT
FOR THE WEAPONS.
IF THE XINDI ARE ON THE WAY,
THERE'S VERY LITTLE WE CAN DO
TO STOP THEM.
WELL, WE CAN'T JUST
RUN UP THE WHITE FLAG.
[ BEEPS ]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN TUCKER.
YOU'D BETTER GET UP HERE, SIR.
I'M ON MY WAY.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THIS LATER.
I'M GETTING A SIGNAL
FROM ONE OF OUR SENTRY PROBES.
SIX XINDI SHIPS
HAVE ENTERED THE SYSTEM.
CHARGE THE PHASE CANNONS.
IS EVERYONE IN POSITION?
AYE, SIR.
THE XINDI SHIPS ARE IN RANGE.
FIRE!
OUR SHIELDS ARE HOLDING.
NICE TO KNOW
THEY WORK IN COMBAT.
REMIND ME TO SEND A THANK-YOU
NOTE TO GENERAL SHRAN.
ADJUST YOUR HEADING.
3-1-0 MARK 27.
FULL IMPULSE.
TWO OF THEIR SHIPS
ARE BREAKING OFF.
THEY'RE FOLLOWING US.
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?
STILL HEADING TOWARD THE PLANET.
THE INSECTOID SHIP'S
BEEN DAMAGED.
-THEY'RE LOSING POWER.
-TARGET THE SECOND ONE.
THEIR ENGINE'S DISABLED.
THE OTHER XINDI SHIPS
HAVE CHANGED THEIR HEADING.
I THINK WE'RE GONNA FIND OUT
HOW MUCH OF A BEATING
THESE NEW SHIELDS CAN TAKE.
T'POL?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
JONATHAN, YOU NEED TO REST.
-WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
-TO THE BRIDGE.
I'M NOT GONNA JUST LIE HERE
WHILE THEY DESTROY
WHAT'S LEFT OF HUMANITY.
YOU SHOULD REMAIN HERE.
FORWARD SHIELDING'S AT 52%.
[ BUZZING ]
TURBOLIFTS ARE DOWN.
INTREPID'S TAKEN A DIRECT HIT.
THEY'VE LOST THEIR PORT NACELLE.
TELL THEM TO WITHDRAW.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
OUR PHASE CANNONS ARE DOWN.
OUR FORWARD SHIELD'S COLLAPSING!
HULL BREACHES ON "B" DECK,
"C" DECK!
THEY'RE TARGETING THE BRIDGE!
HARD TO PORT!
THE BRIDGE IS GONE.
T'POL TO PHLOX.
GO AHEAD.
MEET US IN ENGINEERING.
WE'RE GOING TO FINISH
THE PROCEDURE.
UNDERSTOOD.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME TO WORRY
ABOUT PARASITES RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S NOT NECESSARILY TRUE.
COME WITH ME.
I'LL EXPLAIN.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN,
THE CHAMBER'S BEEN DAMAGED.
DIDN'T YOU SAY WE COULD
DESTROY THE PARASITES
WITH A SUBSPACE IMPLOSION?
-YES, BUT THAT WOULD --
-CAN WE CREATE ONE?
WE WOULD HAVE TO OVERLOAD
THREE PLASMA INJECTORS.
THAT WOULD SEND A FEEDBACK PULSE
THROUGH THE REACTOR.
YOU'LL DESTROY THE SHIP!
AT THIS POINT, IT WON'T MAKE
MUCH OF A DIFFERENCE.
YOU TWO GET TO A SHUTTLEPOD.
THEY'RE ONLY AFTER HUMANS.
IF THIS DOESN'T WORK OUT,
YOU'LL STILL HAVE A CHANCE.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
YOU WERE RELIEVED OF COMMAND.
ONE OF THE PLASMA INJECTORS
WAS DAMAGED.
WE'LL HAVE TO REPLACE IT.
THEY'RE IN SUPPLY LOCKER "C."
ON THE UPPER LEVEL.
WE'RE BACK IN BUSINESS.
AAH!
PHLOX!
PHLOX.
-HOW MUCH LONGER?
-STAND BY.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
LIKE A SHUTTLEPOD
LANDED ON MY HEAD.
WHAT'S OUR STATUS?
WE'VE CLEARED THE ANOMALIES.
THERE'S MINOR DAMAGE
TO THE STARBOARD NACELLE.
REPAIRS SHOULD BE COMPLETE
WITHIN THE HOUR.
YOU SUFFERED A MILD CONCUSSION.
I'D LIKE TO KEEP YOU OVERNIGHT
FOR OBSERVATION.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR.
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN
SERIOUSLY INJURED.
I TOLD YOU TO LEAVE ME BEHIND.
FORTUNATELY,
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU.
I BELIEVE YOU WANTED TO
SEE THIS.
"ROSEMARY'S BABY"?
YOU WERE OBVIOUSLY
LOOKING FORWARD TO IT.
AND SINCE YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
BE ABLE TO ATTEND TONIGHT.
THANKS.
OH, WOULD YOU MIND BRINGING ME
ANOTHER PILLOW?
WOULD YOU TURN DOWN THE LIGHTS
JUST A LITTLE?
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, THAT'S GREAT.
YOU KNOW...
YOU'D MAKE A WONDERFUL NURSE.