ANY LAST WORDS?
GO TO HELL.
DIDN'T KNOW SKAGS
BELIEVED IN HELL.
[ HORSES NEIGHING ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
WHO'S PAYING FOR THE BOX?
I HOPE YOU'RE NOT PLANNING
TO BURY HIM IN THE CEMETERY.
HIS PEOPLE
DON'T BURY THEIR DEAD.
BUT I WOULDN'T
EXPECT YOU TO KNOW THAT.
I'M SORRY I DIDN'T GET THERE
IN TIME TO STOP THEM.
WHAT DIFFERENCE
WOULD IT HAVE MADE?
HE'D HAVE GOTTEN A TRIAL.
AND THE SAME PEOPLE
THAT LYNCHED HIM
WOULD HAVE BEEN
SITTING ON THE JURY.
BETHANY...
HE KILLED A MAN.
SELF-DEFENSE OR NOT, THAT'S
A HANGING OFFENSE FOR A SKAG.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
I'VE CONFIRMED
THAT THEY'RE HUMAN.
THEIR DNA IS A PERFECT MATCH.
LOOKS PRETTY AUTHENTIC, CAPTAIN.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE SPITTOONS.
AND THE HANGINGS.
IF THESE PEOPLE
ARE FROM EARTH...
...HOW THE HELL
DID THEY GET HERE?
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
REPORT.
WE'VE SCANNED
90% OF THE SURFACE.
THE HUMAN SETTLEMENTS
ARE CLUSTERED
WITHIN A FEW HUNDRED KILOMETERS
OF YOUR LOCATION.
ABOUT 6,000 PEOPLE.
-AND THE ALIENS?
-FEWER THAN 1,000.
THEIR CLOSEST ENCAMPMENT
IS 10 KILOMETERS NORTHWEST
OF YOUR PRESENT POSITION.
ANY SIGNS OF TECHNOLOGY?
ENERGY SIGNATURES?
-VESSELS?
-NONE, SIR.
OUR QUANTUM SCANS
PUT THE EARLIEST STRUCTURES
AT OVER 250 YEARS OLD.
THAT SOUNDS ABOUT RIGHT.
BUT THEY'RE ALL CONSTRUCTED
OF MATERIALS
INDIGENOUS TO THE PLANET.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
I WANT YOU TO GO CHECK OUT
THAT ALIEN SETTLEMENT,
SEE WHAT YOU CAN FIND.
THERE'S NO TELLING
HOW ANYONE WOULD REACT
IF THEY FIND OUT
WHO WE REALLY ARE.
KEEP A LOW PROFILE.
AYE, SIR.
[ HORSES WHINNYING ]
MORNING.
CAN I HELP YOU FOLKS?
I HOPE SO.
WE NEED A HORSE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOURS?
EXCUSE ME?
IT'S A LONG WAY
FROM THE NEXT TOWN.
HOW DID YOU GET HERE?
OUR HORSES...PERISHED
SEVERAL MILES
NORTH OF YOUR TOWN.
FROM...HEAT EXHAUSTION.
WELL, YOU'RE LUCKY
THE SUN VIPERS DIDN'T GET YOU.
OR THOSE SKAGS.
COME ON.
THIS ONE HERE,
ONLY FOUR YEARS OLD.
GOOD STOCK.
$20, SHE'S YOURS.
SOUNDS KIND OF STEEP.
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU'D BE
INTERESTED IN A TRADE.
WELL, THAT DEPENDS ON
WHAT YOU GOT TO TRADE.
[ HARMONICA MUSIC PLAYS ]
I HAVEN'T SEEN
ONE OF THESE IN YEARS.
LOOK, UH,
I KNOW IT'S NOT WORTH A HORSE
BUT WE ONLY NEED HIM
FOR A COUPLE HOURS.
WE JUST WANT TO RIDE OUT
AND GRAB OUR GEAR.
WE'LL BE BACK
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT.
UH...
WELL...
HOW ABOUT I LEAVE MY GUN
FOR COLLATERAL?
YOU GOT YOURSELF A DEAL.
HERE, BUDDY.
GO ON.
GO ON, GIRL.
[ NOTES PLAYING ]
DO YOU HAVE ANY EXPERIENCE
RIDING THESE ANIMALS?
I'VE SEEN
EVERY JOHN FORD WESTERN.
WHO?
LOOK, HOW HARD CAN IT BE?
BETTER HOLD ON.
[ HORSE SNORTS ]
-AFTERNOON.
-WHAT CAN I GET YOU?
I'M PASSING THROUGH TOWN.
I WAS HOPING I COULD SIT IN HERE
FOR AWHILE
TILL IT COOLS DOWN.
-COFFEE'S ON THE HOUSE.
-THANKS.
WHERE YOU HEADED?
MY BROTHER'S GOT A RANCH
DOWN SOUTH.
HE SAID HE COULD SET ME UP
WITH SOME WORK.
WHAT'S HE RAISING?
BLUEHORNS?
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
THE LAND DOWN THERE'S NOT GOOD
FOR MUCH ELSE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SEE THE RESEMBLANCE?
WELL, YEAH.
YEAH, I DO.
YOU'RE NOT TELLING ME
YOU'RE RELATED TO COOPER SMITH?
HE'S MY ANCESTOR.
-I'LL BE DAMNED.
-YEP.
YOU'RE LOOKING
AT THE ONLY DIRECT DESCENDANT
OF THE MAN
WHO OVERTHREW THE SKAGS.
I BET YOU'VE GOT SOME STORIES.
-GOT A FEW I COULD TELL YOU.
-[ DOOR OPENS, MEN LAUGHING ]
-YOU BOYS STILL AT IT?
-JUST GETTING STARTED.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S ABOUT OVER.
-FRIENDS OF YOURS?
-NOT PARTICULARLY.
HOW ABOUT A LITTLE SERVICE?
WHAT'LL IT BE?
ANYTHING BUT THAT ROTGUT
YOU WERE POURING YESTERDAY.
WHY DON'T YOU JOIN US?
YOU KNOW I'M NOT ALLOWED
TO DO THAT, MR. BENNINGS.
IT'S DEPUTY BENNINGS.
AND I CAN BEND A LOCAL ORDINANCE
IF I CHOOSE.
HAVE A SEAT.
I IMAGINE YOU COULD USE A DRINK
AFTER WHAT HAPPENED LAST NIGHT.
LET'S RAISE A GLASS...
...TO THE DEARLY DEPARTED.
TO DEAD SKAGS.
[ LAUGHS ]
DRINK UP.
[ COUGHS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
I THOUGHT YOU PEOPLE
COULD HOLD YOUR LIQUOR.
YOUR FRIEND HAD A FEW IN HIM
THE NIGHT HE KILLED
CLAY STANTON.
HE DIDN'T DRINK.
BEG YOUR PARDON?
I'D BETTER GET BACK TO WORK.
NO, NO.
NO, WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T THINK I HEARD YOU RIGHT.
YOU'RE TELLING ME
THAT A SOBER SKAG
HAD THE NERVE TO SHOOT A MAN?
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
I FIND THAT HARD TO BELIEVE.
MAYBE YOU COULD DEMONSTRATE IT.
[ COCKS GUN ]
PICK IT UP.
SHOOT ME.
RIGHT HERE.
BETWEEN THE EYES.
THIS IS
YOUR GOLDEN OPPORTUNITY.
DON'T PASS IT UP.
I KNOW YOU'D LIKE TO KILL ME.
THAT'S WHAT ALL YOU SKAGS WANT,
ISN'T IT?
GO AHEAD.
OR MAYBE YOU NEED TO
FINISH THAT DRINK FIRST.
EXCUSE ME.
DO YOU THINK I COULD GET
SOME MORE COFFEE
BEFORE YOU SHOOT HIM?
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
NAME'S ARCHER.
WELL, MR. ARCHER...
YOU COULD LEARN A THING OR TWO
ABOUT MANNERS.
I DON'T LIKE BEING INTERRUPTED
IN THE MIDDLE OF A CONVERSATION.
-I'LL KEEP THAT IN MIND.
-IS THERE A PROBLEM HERE?
I WAS JUST HAVING A DRINK
WITH OUR FRIEND DRAYSIK,
AND THIS GENTLEMAN
DECIDED TO BUTT IN.
I SAW YOU THIS MORNING
AT THE UNDERTAKER'S.
-WHAT'S YOUR BUSINESS HERE?
-JUST PASSING THROUGH TOWN.
THIS SKAG A FRIEND OF YOURS?
I JUST WANTED HIM
TO GET ME A CUP OF COFFEE.
IT'S A LITTLE HOT FOR COFFEE
TODAY, DON'T YOU THINK?
MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE.
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
MAKE SURE HE LEAVES TOWN.
AND, UH, BENNINGS...
LEAVE THE SKAG ALONE.
I'D ESTIMATE
THIS VESSEL HAS BEEN HERE
FOR AT LEAST TWO CENTURIES.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
THE CAPTAIN SAID
TO LEARN WHATEVER WE COULD.
HE ALSO SAID
TO KEEP A LOW PROFILE.
I PLAN TO.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I DIDN'T MEAN TO STARTLE YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
MY NAME'S JONATHAN ARCHER.
I SAW YOU THIS MORNING,
PAYING FOR THAT MAN'S CASKET.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE YOU'RE FROM,
MR. ARCHER,
BUT AROUND HERE NO ONE REFERS TO
A SKAGARAN AS A MAN.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
OH, CAN I HELP YOU WITH THAT?
I-I'LL MANAGE.
IT'S NO TROUBLE.
I'LL ASK YOU AGAIN.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I'D LIKE TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE SKAGARANS.
EVERYONE KNOWS
THERE AREN'T ANY
WHERE I COME FROM.
WHERE'S THAT?
UP NORTH.
QUITE A WAYS.
IF CERTAIN PEOPLE HAD THEIR WAY,
THERE WOULDN'T BE
ANY AROUND HERE EITHER.
I HEARD ABOUT WHAT YOU DID
IN THE SALOON TODAY.
DEPUTY BENNINGS HAS
A NASTY TEMPER.
WHY WOULD YOU RISK GETTING
THROWN IN JAIL, MAYBE WORSE?
I DON'T THINK
THAT SKAGARAN'S LIFE
IS ANY LESS VALUABLE THAN MINE.
SO...
WHAT DO YOU WANT WITH ME?
WELL...YOU ARE THE TEACHER
AROUND HERE, AREN'T YOU?
THE FIRST SKAGARAN I EVER SAW
WAS TODAY, LYING IN THAT COFFIN.
SEEMS I'D BE MORE LIKELY
TO GET THE TRUTH FROM YOU
THAN FROM THE MEN
WHO PUT HIM THERE.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO MEET
MORE OF THEM?
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
CAPTAIN.
BETHANY.
THESE ARE THE FRIENDS
I TOLD YOU ABOUT.
YOU'RE FROM UP NORTH TOO?
THAT'S CORRECT.
THE CHILDREN WILL BE HERE SOON.
YOU SAID YOU WANTED TO LEARN
SOMETHING, MR. ARCHER.
YOU'RE WELCOME TO STAY
FOR THE LESSON.
THANKS.
KIND OF LATE AT NIGHT
TO BE TEACHING SCHOOL.
IT'S ILLEGAL TO TEACH SKAGARAN.
A SHIP?
WHAT'S LEFT OF IT.
WE FOUND THESE
IN THE DATA MODULE.
GO BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN SALVAGE.
YOU'RE NOT COMING WITH US?
DON'T WANT TO MISS
MY FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL.
9 TIMES 12.
DON'T FORGET TO CARRY THE 1.
YRAL.
-9 TIMES 12 EQUALS 108.
-THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU'RE DOING VERY WELL
WITH YOUR MULTIPLICATION TABLES.
TOMORROW NIGHT
WE'LL START WITH SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE CHALLENGING.
LONG DIVISION.
KRET, COLLECT THE SLATES,
PLEASE.
I BROUGHT A FRIEND WITH ME
WHO'D LIKE TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT YOUR PEOPLE.
WHO CAN TELL MR. ARCHER
HOW THE HUMANS AND THE SKAGARANS
CAME TO LIVE TOGETHER?
TALIYAH?
OUR ANCESTORS TOOK THE HUMANS
FROM THEIR PLANET
AND BROUGHT THEM HERE.
AND WHY DID THEY DO THAT?
TO MAKE THEM WORK.
BUT THE HUMANS
DIDN'T WANT TO WORK
FOR THE SKAGARANS, DID THEY?
-NO...
-[ GASPS ]
WE DIDN'T.
GO ON HOME NOW.
GO ON. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I TRIED TO WARN YOU, BETHANY.
TEACHING SKAGS IS A CRIME.
YOU KNOW THAT.
NO ONE IS BEING HURT HERE.
SO YOU SAY.
BUT I'M AFRAID
THE LAW IS THE LAW.
I THOUGHT YOU COULD BEND
THE LOCAL ORDINANCES.
THAT'S TRUE.
BUT THIS IS ONE I HAVE
NO INTENTION OF BENDING.
GET AWAY FROM ME.
UGH!
SHERIFF GAVE YOU
A CHANCE TO LEAVE TOWN.
YOU SHOULD HAVE TAKEN IT.
[ GLASS BREAKS,
INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
BEST I CAN DO.
THANKS.
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN TO YOU NOW?
DON'T WORRY.
THIS ISN'T THE FIRST TIME
THE SHERIFF AND I
HAVEN'T SEEN EYE TO EYE.
YOU DIDN'T GET TO FINISH
YOUR LESSON.
I'D LIKE TO HEAR THE REST OF IT.
YOU KNOW THE STORY.
EVERYONE DOES.
EVERYONE SEEMS TO HAVE
THEIR OWN VERSION.
I'M CURIOUS TO HEAR
THE WAY YOU TEACH IT
TO THE SKAGARANS.
THAT WRECK
AT THEIR SETTLEMENT --
WAS THAT THEIR SHIP?
THEY USED IT 300 YEARS AGO
TO GO TO EARTH,
BRING OUR ANCESTORS BACK HERE.
THEY WERE BUILDING COLONIES.
THEY NEEDED WORKERS.
YOU MEAN SLAVES?
I-IT WAS A TERRIBLE CRIME.
TELL ME ABOUT COOPER SMITH.
THAT'S WHERE THE STORIES
DIFFER SOMEWHAT.
TO THE HUMANS, HE'S A FOLK HERO.
OUR LIBERATOR.
I'M SURE THAT'S WHAT
YOU WERE TAUGHT.
BUT THE SKAGARANS,
THEY CALL HIM "ROKDAR."
IT MEANS "BUTCHER."
HE AND HIS MEN
BURNED THE SKAGARAN SHIP,
DESTROYED THEIR WEAPONS.
THEY MURDERED MOST OF THEM.
ENTIRE FAMILIES.
HAVE YOU HEARD THAT VERSION?
SMITH WROTE THE FIRST LAWS
THAT KEPT THE SKAGARANS
FROM GOING TO SCHOOL,
OWNING PROPERTY, EVEN MARRYING.
SO THEY COULD NEVER ENSLAVE
THE HUMANS AGAIN.
-[ DOOR OPENS ]
-THAT'S HOW THEY JUSTIFIED IT.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
MEN LIKE BENNINGS ARE HAPPY
TO CARRY ON THE TRADITION.
[ KEYS JINGLING ]
SHERIFF WANTS TO TALK TO YOU.
[ CELL DOOR CLOSES, LOCKS ]
-CARE FOR A SHAVE, MR. ARCHER?
-NO, THANKS.
YOU SURE?
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
A BARBER SHAVE
TO MAKE A MAN FEEL CIVILIZED.
I FEEL CIVILIZED ENOUGH.
WELL, SUIT YOURSELF.
THANKS, HENRY.
ANYTIME, SHERIFF.
HAVE A SEAT.
SKAGARAN WHISKEY.
IT'S ILLEGAL, BUT I LET HENRY
KEEP A BOTTLE AROUND
FOR PULLING TEETH.
PACKS A HELL OF A WALLOP.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
I THOUGHT YOU WERE HEADING SOUTH
TO RAISE BLUEHORNS.
THAT'S THE PLAN.
THEN MAYBE YOU CAN TELL ME
WHY YOU WERE OUT IN SKAGTOWN
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
IS THAT A CRIME?
MY DEPUTY SAYS
YOU AND MISS BETHANY
WERE TEACHING THOSE CHILDREN.
THAT'S A CRIME.
BUT IF I DECIDED TO LYNCH
A SKAGARAN, THAT'D BE LEGAL?
THE LAW WAS LAID DOWN
A LONG TIME AGO
TO PROTECT MEN LIKE YOU AND ME.
PROTECT US FROM WHAT?
CHILDREN?
YOU REALLY WANT THOSE CHILDREN
TO LEARN HOW TO READ?
HOW TO DO THEIR NUMBERS?
AND THEN MAYBE
THEY CAN LEARN ABOUT
HOW THEY USED TO BE
IN CHARGE AROUND HERE.
HOW THEY HAD GUNS THAT COULD
KILL A MAN WITH A BEAM OF LIGHT
AND THAT HUMAN BEINGS
WERE NOTHING
BUT THEIR LABOR FORCE,
THEIR PROPERTY.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT THOSE
CHILDREN TO LEARN, MR. ARCHER?
YOU'RE JUDGING THEM
ON SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED
OVER 200 YEARS AGO.
AND IT'S MY JOB TO MAKE SURE
IT NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
NOW, I'M NOT SAYING IT'S FAIR.
IT'S JUST THE WAY
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
I EXPECT YOU TO BE
OUT OF TOWN IN AN HOUR.
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN TO BETHANY?
SHE'S BEEN WARNED.
SHE KNEW THE CONSEQUENCES.
MINIMUM SENTENCE IS 10 YEARS.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
GO AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
ANY LUCK
WITH THOSE DATA MODULES?
SEVERAL OF THEM WERE DAMAGED,
BUT WE MANAGED TO ACCESS
SOME OF THE LOGS.
I'M STILL WORKING
ON THE TRANSLATION, SIR.
I'LL MEET YOU AT THE LANDING
COORDINATES IN AN HOUR.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I HAVE TO DO FIRST.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
[ KNOCKING CONTINUES ]
I WAS ON MY WAY OUT OF TOWN
AND REALIZED I FORGOT SOMETHING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IT'S CALLED A JAILBREAK
WHERE I COME FROM.
IT'S CALLED THAT HERE TOO.
WHERE DO YOU EXPECT ME TO GO?
THERE ARE OTHER SETTLEMENTS.
I'M SURE THEY CAN USE
A GOOD TEACHER.
THINGS WON'T BE
ANY DIFFERENT THERE.
MAYBE NOT.
BUT YOU WON'T BE SPENDING
10 YEARS IN PRISON.
[ KEYS JINGLING, DOOR LOCKS ]
[ COUGHING ]
IT WAS ARCHER.
[ KEYS JINGLING ]
THEY COULDN'T HAVE GOTTEN FAR.
GET NASH AND FRANKLIN.
OH!
-[ BEEPS ]
-ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
LOCK THE TRANSPORTER
ONTO MY POSITION.
THERE ARE TWO OF US.
DROP THAT!
WHATEVER IT IS.
DID ANYONE SEE YOU TRANSPORT?
I DIDN'T EXACTLY HAVE TIME
TO FIND A SECLUDED SPOT.
THESE ARE VOLATILE
AND SUSPICIOUS PEOPLE.
YOUR DISAPPEARANCE
MAY HAVE CONSEQUENCES.
I'VE REMOVED THE PROJECTILE.
BUT HER INJURIES WERE EXTENSIVE.
-WILL SHE MAKE IT?
-I BELIEVE SO.
BUT THERE ARE A FEW THINGS
ABOUT HER PHYSIOLOGY
I STILL DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
AREN'T YOU FAMILIAR
WITH THIS WOMAN'S ANCESTRY?
THE CRANIAL GENES ARE RECESSIVE,
WHICH EXPLAINS
HER HUMAN APPEARANCE.
MY GUESS IS THEY CAME
FROM HER MATERNAL GRANDMOTHER.
SHE'S ONE-QUARTER SKAGARAN.
YOU HEARD THE STORIES
SAME AS ME.
COOPER SMITH SAID THE SKAGS
COULD MOVE THROUGH THIN AIR
FROM ONE PLACE TO ANOTHER.
MAYBE YOU OUGHT TO GET
YOUR EYES CHECKED, BENNINGS.
ARCHER'S A HUMAN.
-HE'S WORKING WITH THEM.
-YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
THEN WHAT WAS HE DOING
OUT IN SKAGTOWN?
AND WHY'D HE STICK UP FOR
DRAYSIK IN THE SALOON YESTERDAY?
'CAUSE YOU WERE BEING
A HORSE'S ASS.
AND WHO WAS HE TALKING TO
ON THAT LITTLE BOX HE HAD?
IT WAS THE SKAGS.
THEY HELPED HIM ESCAPE.
THIS IS WHAT
WE WERE AFRAID OF, MAC --
THAT THEY'D TRY
TO TAKE OVER AGAIN.
IT'S TIME TO PUT AN END TO THIS.
YOU HAVE SOMETHING IN MIND?
[ SIGHS ]
I SAY WE RIDE OUT THERE TONIGHT
AND BURN 'EM OUT.
I GUARANTEE YOU THERE'LL BE
PLENTY OF VOLUNTEERS.
NOW, YOU LISTEN TO ME.
I'M NOT GONNA
MURDER THOSE PEOPLE
JUST BECAUSE SOME STRANGER
SPOOKED YOU WITH A PARLOR TRICK.
NOW, IF I GET SOME PROOF
THAT THE SKAGARANS
ARE UP TO SOMETHING,
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN
TOO SOFT ON THEM, MAC.
AND YOU'VE ALWAYS
HARASSED THEM
WHILE I LOOKED THE OTHER WAY.
AND THAT'S GONNA CHANGE
RIGHT NOW.
AS LONG AS YOU WORK FOR ME,
OUR JOB IS TO ENFORCE THE LAW.
UNDERSTOOD?
UNDERSTOOD.
THE STORY SHE TOLD YOU
WAS BASICALLY TRUE, CAPTAIN.
THE SKAGARAN SHIP BROUGHT THEM
HERE TO PROVIDE LABOR
FOR A COLONY THEY WERE
TRYING TO ESTABLISH.
THEY APPARENTLY FOUND THE HUMANS
SUITED TO SURVIVE
IN THIS ENVIRONMENT.
THERE ARE A LOT OF REPORTS
OF DISCIPLINARY PROBLEMS.
AND THEN, SIX MONTHS AFTER
THEY ARRIVED, THE LOGS END.
THEY KIDNAPPED THE WRONG PEOPLE.
SO, WHAT DO WE DO?
THEY'RE HUMANS.
WE CAN'T JUST LEAVE THEM HERE.
WE CAN'T TRANSPORT
6,000 PEOPLE BACK TO EARTH.
ONCE WE'VE DEALT WITH THE XINDI,
WE'LL COME BACK HERE
DO WHAT WE CAN TO HELP THEM.
FOR NOW...
THEY DESERVE TO KNOW THAT EARTH
HASN'T ABANDONED THEM.
[ WHIRRING ]
-[ NEIGHS ]
-EASY!
WE NEED TO TALK.
AND YOU WERE BORN THERE?
I WAS BORN IN UPSTATE NEW YORK.
SPENT MOST OF MY ADULT LIFE
IN SAN FRANCISCO, THOUGH.
YOU'VE HEARD OF SAN FRANCISCO?
PACIFIC COAST.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US
WHO YOU WERE?
I WASN'T SURE HOW YOU'D REACT.
WE THOUGHT WE'D BETTER GET
THE LAY OF THE LAND FIRST.
WELL, I CAN'T SAY I BLAME YOU.
A PART OF ME NEVER BELIEVED
EARTH EVEN EXISTED.
I THOUGHT IT WAS SOMETHING
PEOPLE MADE UP
'CAUSE THEY COULDN'T STAND
LIVING HERE.
YOU TAKING US BACK?
WE CAN'T.
NOT RIGHT NOW.
ANYWAY, OUR SHIP
ISN'T BIG ENOUGH.
BUT SOMEDAY WE'LL COME BACK
FOR YOU.
YOU...YOU REALIZE...
IT'S NOT THE SAME WORLD
YOUR ANCESTORS LEFT.
A LOT'S CHANGED IN 300 YEARS.
YOU'RE TELLING ME.
WE'VE MOVED PAST THINGS
LIKE INTOLERANCE, PREJUDICE.
THE SKAGARANS ABDUCTED
MY ANCESTORS, CAPTAIN,
TURNED THEM INTO SLAVES.
THAT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
WELL, WE TEND TO HAVE
A LONG MEMORY
WHEN IT COMES
TO THAT SORT OF THING.
CAPTAIN'S BEEN IN THERE
QUITE AWHILE.
I IMAGINE THE SHERIFF
HAS A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
YEAH.
-WE DID WHAT WE HAD TO DO.
-I UNDERSTAND.
BUT IF YOU DO
MAKE IT BACK TO EARTH,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
LEAVE ALL THAT BEHIND.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THESE FOLKS AREN'T
GONNA HURT ANYBODY.
THIS IS MY FIRST OFFICER, T'POL.
SHE'S FROM A PLANET
CALLED VULCAN.
-PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
-MA'AM.
DR. PHLOX REPORTS THAT HIS
PATIENT IS DOING MUCH BETTER.
GOOD.
I THOUGHT WE'D BRING
MR. MACREADY --
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ SCREAMING,
INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
HAVE YOUR MEN DROP THOSE GUNS.
LET'S TALK THIS
THROUGH, BENNINGS.
I NEVER WAS ONE FOR TALKING.
[ COCKS GUNS ]
[ COCKS GUN ]
TRUST ME, YOU DON'T WANT TO
PICK A FIGHT WITH US, DEPUTY.
SHOULD'VE THOUGHT OF THAT BEFORE
YOU THREW IN WITH THE SKAGS.
WE'RE NOT TAKING SIDES HERE.
THEN WHERE DID YOU GET
THAT MACHINE AND THOSE WEAPONS?
THESE PEOPLE ARE
FROM EARTH, BENNINGS.
EARTH?
YOU'RE LYING.
I CAN PROVE IT TO YOU.
JUST GIVE ME A CHANCE.
[ RIFLE COCKS ]
GO.
LAY DOWN SOME FIRE.
-[ THUD ]
-[ T'POL GROANS ]
STAY BACK.
I'LL KILL HER.
SECURE THE AREA!
FIND THE CAPTAIN!
[ HORSE NEIGHS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
WE'RE UP TOO HIGH TO SEE IT,
BUT YOUR TOWN IS DOWN THERE.
TOWARD THE RIGHT EDGE
OF THAT MOUNTAIN RANGE.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
I FEEL FINE.
NOT EVEN A SCAR.
DR. PHLOX DOES EXCELLENT WORK.
YOU MUST THINK WE'RE BARBARIC.
ALL THE THINGS
HUMANITY HAS ACCOMPLISHED --
BUILDING SHIPS LIKE THIS,
TRAVELING TO OTHER WORLDS.
AND WE'RE STILL DOWN THERE
SHOOTING EACH OTHER.
THE PROGRESS ON EARTH,
IT DIDN'T HAPPEN OVERNIGHT.
BUT IT WAS PROGRESS
ALL THE SAME.
YOU'VE MANAGED TO CHANGE.
WE HAVEN'T.
EVEN IF YOU COULD TAKE US BACK,
I DON'T THINK WE'RE READY.
IT MAY BE AWHILE
BEFORE WE'RE ABLE
TO START SENDING SHIPS HERE.
MY GUESS IS,
BY THE TIME THEY ARRIVE,
THEY'LL FIND
THINGS HAVE CHANGED.
I THINK YOU'RE GIVING US
TOO MUCH CREDIT.
IT'S HAPPENING ALREADY.
I SPOKE WITH MACREADY.
HE AGREES THAT,
IN LIGHT OF RECENT EVENTS,
SOME OF YOUR LAWS
MIGHT BE A LITTLE OUTDATED.
BEFORE PEOPLE COULD TRAVEL
THROUGH SPACE TO OTHER PLANETS,
THEY HAD TO
GET OFF THE GROUND FIRST.
ALMOST 40 YEARS AFTER
MY HUMAN ANCESTORS LEFT EARTH,
TWO BROTHERS FROM OHIO
BECAME THE FIRST HUMAN BEINGS
TO BUILD
A SUCCESSFUL FLYING MACHINE.
THEIR NAMES WERE
ORVILLE AND WILBUR WRIGHT.
WOULD ANYONE LIKE TO SEE
A PICTURE OF THEIR AIRPLANE?
-ME!
-YES'M.
OH, YOU ALL WOULD.
WELL, HERE IT IS, RIGHT HERE.
AND YOU CAN SEE,
HERE'S ORVILLE WRIGHT,
AND HIS BROTHER, WILBUR,
IS FLYING THE PLANE.
NOW, THIS IS A MACHINE
THAT ACTUALLY...