THE MOST DIFFICULT TEST
FACING ANY CAPTAIN, ANY CREW,
IS THE LOSS OF A SHIPMATE.
WE HAVE COME HERE
TO HONOR ONE OF OUR OWN.
IN THE TIME WE KNEW HIM,
HE SHOWED US JUST HOW MUCH
ONE LIFE CAN TRULY MATTER.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET
WHAT HE DID FOR US
AND FOR THE SHIP
HE LOVED SO MUCH.
WE WILL GO FORWARD
WITH RENEWED DETERMINATION
TO COMPLETE THIS MISSION,
SO THAT HIS SACRIFICE
WON'T JUST HAVE BEEN
FOR THE PEOPLE ON THIS SHIP
BUT FOR ALL THE CITIZENS
OF EARTH.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
WE JUST REROUTE THE SYSTEM TAPS,
COMPRESS THE ANTIMATTER STREAM
BEFORE IT
REACHES THE INJECTORS.
THAT WILL STABILIZE
THE WARP FIELD?
EVERY SIMULATION I RUN
COMES BACK
WITH THE SAME RESULT.
WE'LL BE ABLE TO CRUISE
AT WARP 5.0
WITH NO FIELD FLUCTUATION.
I'M TALKING ABOUT
A RIDE SO SMOOTH,
YOU CAN BUILD A HOUSE OF CARDS
ON THE WARP REACTOR.
IF WE CAN MAINTAIN HIGH WARP
FOR EXTENDED PERIODS,
WE CAN COVER THE EXPANSE
MORE QUICKLY.
WHICH BOOSTS OUR CHANCES
OF FINDING THE XINDI WEAPON
IN TIME.
[ GASPS ]
TO THE LEFT.
OH, SORRY.
YOU GET ME TALKING
ABOUT THE ENGINES,
AND I FORGET WHERE I AM.
DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS
ABOUT FINE-TUNING
A PIECE OF MACHINERY.
LIE ON YOUR BACK.
YOU KNOW, YOU MADE THIS SOUND
A WHOLE LOT WORSE THAN IT IS.
ADVANCED NEUROPRESSURE CAN PLACE
GREAT DEMANDS ON THE BODY.
WELL, I HAVE TO SAY
SO FAR IT'S A PIECE OF CAKE.
WE HAVEN'T GOTTEN TO
THE MORE CHALLENGING POSTURES.
WELL...
I'M ALWAYS UP FOR A CHALLENGE.
BREATHE.
-TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE.
-SIR.
ARCHER.
WE'RE ALL SET DOWN HERE.
I'LL NEED AT LEAST 4.9
TO GET THE PLASMA HOT ENOUGH
TO COMPRESS THE STREAM.
YOU HEARD THE MAN, TRAVIS.
4.9.
AYE, SIR.
4.5.
4.6.
4.7.
4.8.
[ RUMBLING ]
THE WARP FIELD IS FLUCTUATING.
4.9.
INITIALIZING STREAM COMPRESSION.
[ RUMBLING STOPS ]
DAMN.
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL SOUND.
FIELD FLUCTUATIONS
HAVE DROPPED TO ZERO.
I THINK WE JUST GOT
OUR SECOND WIND.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
SOMETHING'S FLOODING
THE INTAKE MANIFOLDS.
-DROP TO IMPULSE.
-I'VE LOST HELM CONTROL.
TRIP, STATUS.
I'VE GOT
A PRIMARY INJECTOR FLARE.
I'M SHUTTING DOWN.
IT'S NOT RESPONDING, CAPTAIN.
THE FLARE IS CAUSING
A SYSTEM-WIDE OVERLOAD.
FIRES REPORTED
ON "B" AND "C" DECK.
EMERGENCY CREWS EN ROUTE.
HELM CONTROL IS STILL DOWN.
-ANALYSIS.
-SOME KIND OF POLARIC FIELD.
APPROXIMATELY 11,000 KILOMETERS
IN DIAMETER.
COMPOSITION UNKNOWN.
I'LL NEED MORE TIME TO COMPLETE
A DETAILED SCAN.
IS THAT WHAT STOPPED US?
IT'S A LOGICAL CONCLUSION.
KEEP SCANNING.
NUMEROUS INJURIES
THROUGHOUT THE SHIP.
MOSTLY MINOR, EXCEPT FOR ONE.
COMMANDER TUCKER
HE HAS BEEN TAKEN TO SICK BAY.
REPORT.
WHEN WE ENTERED THE FIELD,
NUCLEONIC PARTICLES
FLOODED THE MANIFOLDS,
CAUSING THE INJECTOR FLARE.
IF COMMANDER TUCKER
HADN'T SHUT DOWN THE REACTOR,
WE COULD HAVE HAD A BREACH.
HOW MUCH TIME BEFORE WE CAN
GET THE ENGINES BACK ONLINE?
WE'RE STILL RUNNING DIAGNOSTICS.
THE DAMAGE IS SIGNIFICANT.
IT COULD TAKE WEEKS.
COMMANDER TUCKER IS GOING TO
HAVE HIS HANDS FULL.
YOU'LL BE SUPERVISING
THE REPAIRS.
I'VE JUST COME FROM SICK BAY.
TRIP'S IN A COMA.
HE HAS EXTENSIVE NEURAL DAMAGE.
DR. PHLOX SAYS
WE HAVE TO PREPARE
FOR THE POSSIBILITY
THAT TRIP WON'T SURVIVE.
HOW IS HE?
HIS CONDITION IS UNCHANGED.
I'D LIKE TO SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
THIS IS ONE OF
THE MORE INTERESTING MEMBERS
OF MY LITTLE MENAGERIE.
A LYSSARRIAN DESERT LARVAE.
ITS EPIDERMAL LAYER
SECRETES A VIRAL SUPPRESSANT
THAT I USE AS A SALVE
FOR CUTS AND BRUISES.
HOW DOES THIS RELATE TO TRIP?
THE LARVAE HAVE ANOTHER
SOMEWHAT, UH,
MORE CONTROVERSIAL PROPERTY.
WHEN IMPLANTED WITH DNA
FROM ANOTHER SPECIES
IT EXACTLY REPLICATES
THAT SPECIES' LIFE CYCLE,
ALBEIT AT
A RAPIDLY ACCELERATED RATE.
-IT BECOMES A CLONE.
-ESSENTIALLY.
BUT ONE THAT IS BORN, GROWS OLD,
AND DIES
IN APPROXIMATELY 15 DAYS.
THE LYSSARRIANS CALL THEM
MIMETIC SIMBIOTS.
THEY'RE A CLOSELY
GUARDED SECRET.
VERY FEW PEOPLE KNOW
OF THEIR EXISTENCE.
AND YOU WANT TO
DO THIS WITH TRIP?
USE HIS DNA TO GROW A SIMBIOT?
TO HARVEST ITS NEURAL TISSUE
FOR A TRANSPLANT.
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE THAT
HUMAN DNA WILL STIMULATE
THE LARVAE'S GROWTH CYCLE.
BUT, UH, AS IT STANDS NOW,
IT MAY BE COMMANDER TUCKER'S
ONLY HOPE FOR SURVIVAL.
TO ENSURE
THE TISSUE'S COMPATIBILITY,
I'LL HAVE TO WAIT
UNTIL THE SIMBIOT
REACHES COMMANDER TUCKER'S
PRESENT PHYSICAL AGE.
THEN I CAN EXCISE THE TISSUE
FROM A NONCRITICAL REGION
OF THE SIMBIOT'S CEREBRUM.
IT WOULD EXPERIENCE
NO DISCERNIBLE SIDE EFFECTS,
AND SHOULD BE ABLE TO
LIVE OUT ITS NORMAL LIFESPAN.
ITS 15-DAY LIFESPAN.
I DON'T MAKE THIS PROPOSAL
LIGHTLY, CAPTAIN,
BUT I'M OBLIGATED TO PROVIDE YOU
WITH ALL AVAILABLE OPTIONS.
[ SIGHS ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
WE SENT OUT AN E.V. TEAM.
THEY RETRIEVED A SAMPLE
OF THE SUBSTANCE
ACCUMULATING ON THE HULL.
MULTIPLE HITS
WITH A PLASMA RIFLE
WERE REQUIRED TO DISLODGE IT.
IT'S COMPOSED OF
HIGHLY CHARGED PARTICLES.
MOSTLY FERRIC IONS.
BUT THERE ARE SEVERAL ELEMENTS
THAT WE CAN'T IDENTIFY.
AND IT'S HIGHLY MAGNETIC.
SO FAR THE DANGER TO THE SHIP
SEEMS NEGLIGIBLE.
BUT THE LONGER
WE REMAIN IN THE FIELD,
THE MORE THESE PARTICLES
BUILD UP.
DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO DO.
BUT WE NEED TO GET THOSE ENGINES
BACK ONLINE.
UNDERSTOOD.
REGARDING THE
LYSSARRIAN PROCEDURE
DR. PHLOX PROPOSED,
MAY I ASK
IF YOU'VE REACHED A DECISION?
I APPROVED IT.
ARE YOU AWARE THAT
THE LYSSARRIAN PRIME CONCLAVE
HAS BANNED THE CREATION
OF SIMBIOTS?
WE DON'T ANSWER TO
THE LYSSARRIAN PRIME CONCLAVE.
SIMBIOTS ARE LIVING,
CONSCIOUS ENTITIES.
WE'LL BE GROWING
A SENTIENT BEING
FOR THE SOLE PURPOSE
OF HARVESTING TISSUE.
I'M AWARE OF
THE ETHICAL IMPLICATIONS.
IF WE WEREN'T IN THE EXPANSE,
MAYBE MY DECISION
WOULD BE DIFFERENT, BUT...
WE'VE GOT TO COMPLETE
THIS MISSION.
EARTH NEEDS ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE NEEDS TRIP.
IT'S AS SIMPLE AS THAT.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE ENGINES ARE STILL DOWN,
AND THE NUCLEONIC PARTICLES
CONTINUE TO BUILD UP
ON THE HULL.
IT'S BEEN TWO DAYS
SINCE DR. PHLOX
INITIATED THE PROCEDURE
TO GROW THE SIMBIOT.
IT'S RATHER SENSITIVE TO LIGHT
AT THIS STAGE.
BY TOMORROW MORNING,
IF ALL GOES WELL,
WE'LL HAVE A HEALTHY BABY BOY
ON OUR HANDS.
[ BABY CRYING ]
A PERFECT GENETIC DUPLICATE,
RIGHT DOWN TO THE BIRTHMARK
ON HIS RIGHT SIDE.
HE CERTAINLY SOUNDS HEALTHY.
AND HUNGRY.
EXCUSE ME.
THERE, THERE.
OH, IT'S BEEN SOME TIME
SINCE I'VE HANDLED A NEWBORN.
OH...
AH.
BUT I SEE
I HAVEN'T LOST MY TOUCH.
THREE DAYS AGO, HE WAS JUST
ANOTHER ONE OF YOUR CREATURES,
SOMETHING YOU KEPT ON A SHELF.
HE'S CERTAINLY COME A LONG WAY
IN A SHORT TIME.
IN A SHORT TIME,
HE'LL BE A LOT OLDER.
HAVE YOU THOUGHT OF
WHERE HE'S GOING TO LIVE?
WHY NOT RIGHT HERE?
I CAN'T THINK OF A MORE
STIMULATING ENVIRONMENT
FOR A DEVELOPING YOUNG MIND.
AND I'LL BE ABLE
TO KEEP A CLOSE WATCH
ON HIS DEVELOPMENT.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE FOUND
YOURSELF A NEW ROOMMATE.
NOW ALL I NEED TO DO
IS FIND HIM A NAME.
THE CREW'S BEEN
OFFERING SUGGESTIONS,
BUT NOTHING SOUNDS RIGHT.
STEVEN. ENRIQUE.
DENNIS. DENNIS?
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU SEE MY DILEMMA.
I'M SURE
YOU'LL THINK OF SOMETHING.
CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER'S LOG.
AFTER MUCH DELIBERATION,
I HAVE FINALLY THOUGHT OF A NAME
FOR THIS NEWEST ADDITION
TO OUR CREW.
[ BABY CRYING ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT, SIM.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LUCKY FOR ME, DENOBULANS
REQUIRE VERY LITTLE SLEEP.
I AM AT LOSS TO UNDERSTAND
HOW HUMAN ADULTS ENDURE
THE R.E.M. CYCLE INTERRUPTIONS
THAT ACCOMPANY
THE TEETHING STAGE.
THOUGH I KNEW WHAT TO EXPECT,
I CAN'T HELP BUT BE ASTONISHED
BY SIM'S RAPID
PHYSICAL DEVELOPMENT.
A SIDE NOTE --
I MAY HAVE STUMBLED ACROSS
AN EFFECTIVE FERTILIZER
FOR MY ORSIC FERN.
"THOSE WHO HAVE NEVER SEEN
A LIVING MARTIAN
"CAN SCARCELY IMAGINE
THE STRANGE HORROR
OF ITS APP-- APPEARANCE."
THAT IS VERY GOOD.
CAN WE JUST SKIP TO THE PART
WHERE THE MARTIAN
MACHINES ATTACK?
WE JUST SHOWED YOU THIS BOOK.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THE MARTIAN MACHINES?
MY MOM READ IT TO ME.
-YOUR MOM?
-UH-HUH.
I THINK IT'S CHAPTER 10.
IT'S BECOME QUITE EVIDENT
THAT SIM'S REMARKABLE
SCHOLASTIC PROGRESS
GOES FAR BEYOND
AN APTITUDE FOR LEARNING.
HE'S REMEMBERING THINGS
THAT HAPPENED TO TRIP
WHEN TRIP WAS THIS AGE.
SO THE OLDER HE GROWS,
THE MORE OF TRIP'S LIFE
HE'LL RECALL?
THERE ARE SOME SPECIES THAT RELY
SOLELY ON GENETIC SEQUENCING
TO PASS ON
THEIR CULTURAL MEMORIES.
EVIDENTLY, HUMANS HAVE
A SIMILAR CAPACITY.
THIS COULD BE
AN IMPORTANT DISCOVERY.
HE CERTAINLY POSSESSES
COMMANDER TUCKER'S CURIOSITY.
THIS MORNING, HE TOOK APART
MY MEDICAL TRICORDER.
HE'S STARTING TO LOOK LIKE TRIP.
AND HE'S BEGINNING
TO ASK QUESTIONS.
"WHERE DID I COME FROM?
WHERE IS MY MOTHER AND FATHER?
WHY AM I HERE?"
IT'S ONLY BEEN THREE DAYS,
AND HE'S ALREADY BEGINNING
TO REALIZE HOW DIFFERENT HE IS.
HE IS GOING TO HAVE TO
BE TOLD THE TRUTH.
SOON.
I GAVE THE ORDER
THAT CREATED HIM.
I SHOULD BE THE ONE
TO EXPLAIN WHY.
THERE'S NOTHING PORTHOS LIKES
MORE THAN DINNERTIME.
CAN HE DO ANY TRICKS?
I HAVEN'T TAUGHT HIM ANY.
MOSTLY WHAT HE DOES IS EAT,
SLEEP, AND, UH, NOT FETCH.
-JUST FILL IT UP HALFWAY.
-OKAY.
I USED TO HAVE A DOG.
HIS NAME WAS BEDFORD.
HE WAS SO BIG,
I COULD RIDE HIM LIKE A HORSE.
IS THAT RIGHT?
THAT'S ZEFRAM COCHRANE.
HE INVENTED WARP DRIVE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HE DID.
DR. PHLOX SAYS YOUR DAD
HELPED DESIGN THE WARP 5 ENGINE.
THAT'S A PICTURE OF HIM
RIGHT THERE.
AND THIS IS ME ON MY FIRST DAY
OF FLIGHT SCHOOL.
DID YOU ALWAYS WANT TO BE
A STARSHIP CAPTAIN?
AS LONG AS I CAN REMEMBER.
WHY?
IT'S WHAT I WAS MEANT TO DO.
BET IT'S A FUN JOB.
IT HAS ITS MOMENTS.
LET ME SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
KEEP THE NOSE UP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT PULLS A LITTLE TO THE LEFT.
TRIM THE PORT AILERON.
THAT FEELS BETTER.
MY DAD SAYS
I SHOULD BE AN ENGINEER.
MY MOM THINKS
I SHOULD STUDY ARCHITECTURE.
BUT I WANT TO DO WHAT YOU DO --
BE A STARSHIP CAPTAIN.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S WEIRD?
WHAT?
MY PARENTS CALL ME TRIP,
BUT EVERYONE HERE CALLS ME SIM.
WHERE'S MY MOM AND DAD?
ARE THEY BACK ON EARTH?
THAT'S A LITTLE DIFFICULT
TO ANSWER.
[ BARKS ]
IT'S BROKEN.
NOTHING A LITTLE GLUE
WON'T REMEDY.
I CRASHED IT
PLENTY OF TIMES MYSELF.
I MISS MY PARENTS.
COME WITH ME.
DR. PHLOX SAYS I'M NOT ALLOWED
TO GO IN THERE.
IT'S OKAY.
HE'S TRIP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MY PARENTS...
THEY'RE NOT REALLY MINE.
THEY'RE HIS.
YES.
SO...
THAT TIME I PUT A GARDEN SNAKE
IN LIZZIE'S DOLLHOUSE...
THAT WASN'T ME.
NO.
SO I'M JUST
SOME KIND OF COPY OF HIM.
YOU'RE MORE THAN THAT, SIM.
YOU HAVE TRIP'S MEMORIES.
BUT YOU ALSO HAVE
YOUR OWN MEMORIES,
THE ONES YOU'RE MAKING HERE
ON ENTERPRISE.
HOW LONG HAVE I LIVED HERE?
YOU WERE BORN
ONLY FOUR DAYS AGO.
I FEEL OLDER.
IT'S HARD TO UNDERSTAND,
I KNOW.
THERE'S PART OF YOU,
SOMETHING INSIDE YOU,
THAT TRIP NEEDS.
DR. PHLOX IS GOING TO HAVE
TO PERFORM AN OPERATION.
-WILL IT HURT?
-NOT AT ALL.
YOU WON'T FEEL A THING.
DOCTORS ALWAYS SAY THAT.
WHEN PHLOX SAYS IT,
IT'S THE TRUTH.
CAN WE GO FIX THE MODEL NOW?
SURE.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
ENTERPRISE HAS BEEN
INCAPACITATED FOR SEVEN DAYS.
AND DURING THAT TIME,
SIM HAS PRACTICALLY BECOME
A MEMBER OF THE CREW.
I'VE ASSIGNED HIM
TO ENGINEERING,
WHERE HE'S BEEN ASSISTING T'POL
IN THE ONGOING EFFORT
TO REPAIR THE ENGINES.
WAVE GUIDES.
FOR THE PRIMARY PORT BYPASS.
THINK I MADE SOME PROGRESS.
THIS LOOKS PROMISING.
THEY'RE SHOWING
"A NIGHT AT THE OPERA" TONIGHT.
MARX BROTHERS.
I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU'RE PLANNING TO GO.
I'LL BE REVIEWING
THE FIELD-COIL EQUATIONS.
THEY NEED TO BE FINISHED IN TIME
FOR TOMORROW'S REACTOR TEST.
OH.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT DINNER?
YOU WANT TO GRAB A BITE?
I APPRECIATE THE OFFER,
BUT I'M AFRAID I HAVE TO WORK
LATE INTO THE EVENING.
ENSIGN MASSARO
IS RUNNING A DIAGNOSTIC
ON THE PLASMA ASSEMBLY.
I'D LIKE YOU TO ASSIST HER.
YES, MA'AM.
IT'S BECAUSE I'M DIFFERENT,
ISN'T IT?
THE REASON YOU DON'T WANT TO DO
ANYTHING WITH ME.
I GUESS IT MUST BE WEIRD
BEING WITH SOMEONE LIKE ME.
FIVE DAYS AGO
I WAS WEARING DIAPERS.
I SIMPLY BELIEVE THAT
OUR ATTENTION SHOULD BE FOCUSED
ON THE SHIP'S ENGINES.
AT LEAST UNTIL THE CURRENT
SITUATION IS RESOLVED.
I PROBABLY WON'T BE AROUND
AFTER THE CURRENT SITUATION
IS RESOLVED.
-[ BEEPS ]
-ARCHER TO T'POL.
GO AHEAD.
WOULD YOU PLEASE COME
TO MY READY ROOM?
ON MY WAY.
WARP DRIVE SHOULD BE FUNCTIONAL
IN TWO WEEKS.
I'M AFRAID
THAT WON'T BE SOON ENOUGH.
-SIR, I --
-ACCORDING TO MALCOLM...
THE ACCUMULATION ON THE HULL
IS GENERATING
A DIAMAGNETIC FIELD.
IT'S HAVING A DAMPENING EFFECT.
THE MORE
THE PARTICULATE BUILDS UP,
THE MORE POWERFUL
THE FIELD BECOMES.
IN ANOTHER FOUR DAYS,
EVERY SYSTEM ON THE SHIP
WILL BE OFF-LINE.
IF WE DON'T MAKE IT OUT OF HERE
BY THEN, WE NEVER WILL.
KEY LIME PIE.
I SUDDENLY REALIZED
IT WAS MY FAVORITE DESSERT.
NOW I KNOW WHY.
DO THESE MEMORIES
JUST COME TO YOU?
WELL, THE OLDER I GET,
THE MORE I REMEMBER.
IT'S LIKE I'VE LIVED
THIS WHOLE OTHER LIFE.
CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
I CAN'T IMAGINE IT.
YOU WANTED TO ASK ME
ABOUT SOMETHING.
MM.
YEAH, I DID.
DO YOU THINK IT'S POSSIBLE
TO REDIRECT THE PHASE CANNONS
SO THEY CAN FIRE BACK
ONTO THE HULL?
I SUPPOSE SO.
WHY?
WELL, I WANT TO TRY AND BLAST
OFF ENOUGH OF THAT PARTICULATE
SO WE CAN OPEN UP
THE LAUNCH BAY DOORS.
IS SOMEONE PLANNING
ON GOING SOMEWHERE?
ALL WE NEED TO DO
IS BUILD UP ENOUGH MOMENTUM
TO GET THE SHIP
OUT OF HERE, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
WELL, WE'VE GOT
TWO PERFECTLY GOOD ENGINES
SITTING IN THE LAUNCH BAY.
IF WE STRING
A COUPLE OF GRAPPLER LINES
BETWEEN THE SHUTTLEPODS
AND THE SHIP,
WE CAN TOW OURSELVES CLEAR.
THE SHUTTLEPODS DON'T GENERATE
THAT KIND OF THRUST.
WE'D NEVER BUILD UP
ENOUGH MOMENTUM
TO GET CLEAR
OF THE FIELD IN TIME.
LEAVE THAT TO ME.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
CAN I COME IN?
DID YOU HAVE A CHANCE
TO LOOK AT MY CALCULATIONS?
I REVIEWED THEM THOROUGHLY.
AND?
A FUSION OVERBURN
HAS NEVER BEEN ATTEMPTED
WITH A SHUTTLEPOD ENGINE.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN IT WON'T WORK.
I AGREE.
DESPITE THE RISKS, I BELIEVE
IT'S OUR BEST OPTION.
SO YOU'RE GONNA RECOMMEND
THE PLAN TO THE CAPTAIN?
I ALREADY HAVE.
WAS THERE SOMETHING ELSE?
YOU AND TRIP USED TO SPEND
A LOT OF TIME HERE TOGETHER.
I WAS INSTRUCTING HIM
IN THE PRACTICE
OF VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE.
I REMEMBER.
WE WERE LYING RIGHT THERE,
WORKING THE NEURAL NODES
ON EACH OTHER'S FEET,
TALKING ABOUT THE WARP ENGINES.
HOW I WAS HOPING TO MODIFY THEM.
HOW COMMANDER TUCKER
WAS HOPING TO MODIFY THEM.
RIGHT.
COMMANDER TUCKER.
YOU KNOW, HE WAS REALLY
STARTING TO ENJOY
THOSE SESSIONS WITH YOU.
THEY WERE HELPING HIM SLEEP.
I'M NOT SURE
THAT'S THE ONLY REASON.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WAS THERE EVER ANYTHING
BETWEEN YOU AND TRIP?
IF YOU'RE REFERRING TO
A ROMANTIC RELATIONSHIP, NO.
THE REASON I ASK IS...
WELL...
YOU'RE ALL I THINK ABOUT,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
AND I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT
AN ADOLESCENT CRUSH.
THAT WAS...
WELL, THAT WAS TWO DAYS AGO.
THIS IS MUCH MORE SERIOUS,
THE WAY I FEEL ABOUT YOU.
ANYWAY...
WHAT'S DRIVING ME CRAZY
IS I DON'T KNOW
IF THESE FEELINGS ARE MINE...
OR HIS.
I CAN'T ANSWER THAT.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO MAKE YOU
FEEL UNCOMFORTABLE.
I'M NOT UNCOMFORTABLE.
I JUST THOUGHT
I SHOULD TELL YOU THIS.
WHILE I STILL HAD THE CHANCE.
-[ DOOR CHIMES ]
-COME IN.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I WANT TO PILOT
ONE OF THE SHUTTLEPODS.
-THAT'S OUT OF THE QUESTION.
-IT'S MY PLAN.
I THINK I SHOULD HAVE A SAY
IN HOW IT'S IMPLEMENTED.
THIS IS A DANGEROUS PROCEDURE.
YOU'VE NEVER FLOWN
A SHUTTLEPOD BEFORE.
YES, I HAVE.
TRIP HAS THOUSANDS OF HOURS
OF FLYING TIME,
AND I HAVE HIS MEMORIES.
I CAN'T JEOPARDIZE THIS SHIP
ON THE STRENGTH
OF THOSE MEMORIES.
MAYWEATHER AND REED
WILL PILOT THE SHUTTLEPODS.
I WANT YOU TO COORDINATE
FROM THE BRIDGE.
T'POL WILL ASSIST YOU.
YOU'RE WORRIED SOMETHING
WILL HAPPEN TO ME, AREN'T YOU?
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE I'M AROUND
BECAUSE YOU NEED
PART OF MY BRAIN.
YEAH.
THAT'S PART OF IT.
SO YOUR CONCERN FOR MY SAFETY
IS REALLY ABOUT SAVING TRIP.
MY MAIN CONCERN
IS THAT THIS PLAN WORK.
IF WE DON'T MAKE IT OUT OF HERE
IN THE NEXT SIX HOURS,
IT WON'T MATTER
WHETHER TRIP SURVIVES OR NOT.
WE'LL ALL BE DEAD.
I'VE REALIGNED
THE TARGETING SCANNERS.
THEY'RE SET FOR CLOSE PROXIMITY.
PHASE CANNONS ARE CHARGED
AND READY.
TRY THE DOORS.
-[ BUZZING ]
-THEY'RE STILL FROZEN.
ARCHER TO
SHUTTLEPODS 1 AND 2.
YOU ARE CLEAR TO LAUNCH.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
SHUTTLEPOD 2, ACKNOWLEDGED.
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY.
SET THE OVERBURN RATIO.
WE'LL START AT 0.175.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
0.175.
PREPARE TO INITIATE ON MY MARK.
NOW.
1,000 KILODYNES.
THRUST VECTOR HOLDING STEADY.
COME ON.
2,000 KILODYNES.
ENGINE TEMPERATURE'S RISING.
I'M READING ZERO
FORWARD MOMENTUM.
2,500 KILODYNES.
ENGINE TEMPERATURE
IS NEARING CRITICAL.
WE'RE STILL NOT MOVING.
COME ON.
INCREASE THE OVERBURN RATIO
ANOTHER 30%.
CAPTAIN?
GO AHEAD.
INCREASING 30%.
[ BEEPING ]
I'VE GOT
A TEMPERATURE WARNING LIGHT.
[ BEEPING ]
I'M READING 500 DEGREES
ABOVE CRITICAL.
THEIR SYSTEMS ARE OVERLOADING.
-SIM...
-A FEW MORE SECONDS.
THEY WON'T LAST A FEW SECONDS.
SORRY, SIM.
ARCHER TO THE SHUTTLEPODS...
[ RUMBLING ]
WE'RE MOVING.
.62 KILOMETERS PER HOUR.
12 KILOMETERS PER HOUR
AND ACCELERATING.
HOW MUCH DO WE NEED?
AT THIS SPEED, WE'LL EMERGE
FROM THE FIELD IN 6.1 HOURS.
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH.
ARCHER TO SHUTTLEPODS 1 AND 2.
COME ON HOME.
WELL DONE.
THANKS, CAPTAIN.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME?
THERE'S BEEN A DEVELOPMENT.
I'M LISTENING.
SIM WON'T SURVIVE
THE TRANSPLANT.
YOU TOLD ME
YOU CAN REMOVE THE TISSUE
WITHOUT HARMING HIM.
THAT ASSESSMENT WAS BASED
ON SIMBIOTS GROWN
FROM LYSSARRIAN DNA.
MY TESTS ON SIM SHOW
THAT HUMAN-BASED SIMBIOTS
ARE NOT AS RESILIENT.
IF I EXCISE THE QUANTITY
OF NEURAL TISSUE I NEED
TO SAVE COMMANDER TUCKER...
...SIM WILL DIE.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
WHY NOT GIVE UP MY LIFE?
I'VE ONLY GOT...
FIVE, SIX DAYS LEFT ANYWAY.
THAT ISN'T HOW WE SEE IT.
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING, DOC.
WHEN YOU RESEARCHED
LYSSARRIAN LARVAE,
DID YOU COME ACROSS
ANY REFERENCES
TO THE VELANDRAN CIRCLE?
THEY WERE A GROUP OF
LYSSARRIAN SCIENTISTS
WHO CONDUCTED ILLEGAL
EXPERIMENTS ON SIMBIOTS.
THEY CLAIMED TO HAVE
DEVELOPED AN ENZYME
THAT STOPPED
THE RAPID AGING PROCESS.
IS THERE ANY TRUTH TO IT?
WHY DO YOU THINK
HE KEPT IT A SECRET?
DOCTOR?
THE ENZYME IS EXPERIMENTAL,
WITH VERY LITTLE
EMPIRICAL EVIDENCE
TO SUGGEST THAT IT WORKS.
THAT'S WHY I DIDN'T MENTION IT.
THERE'S NOT MUCH EVIDENCE,
BUT IT EXISTS.
THE FACT IS, I MAY NOT HAVE TO
GROW OLD AND DIE IN A WEEK.
THERE'S A CHANCE THAT I CAN
LIVE OUT A NORMAL LIFESPAN.
I CAN'T CHANGE
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM.
BUT MAYBE I CAN CHANGE
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN TO ME.
-[ DOOR CHIMES ]
-COME IN.
HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN STAYING HERE?
I WAS ON THE WAY
TO MY ROOM LAST NIGHT, BUT...
I CAME HERE INSTEAD.
THESE ARE TRIP'S QUARTERS.
WHICH IS WHERE I BELONG.
I HAVE HIS MEMORIES.
I HAVE HIS FEELINGS.
I HAVE HIS BODY.
HOW AM I NOT TRIP?
COMMANDER TUCKER
IS LYING IN SICK BAY.
THEN WHAT AM I?
JUST SOMETHING
YOU GREW IN A LAB?
DOES THAT MAKE IT EASIER FOR YOU
TO CONDEMN ME TO DEATH?
IF YOU REFUSE TO GO THROUGH
WITH THIS,
YOU'LL BE CONDEMNING TRIP
TO DEATH.
-I DIDN'T PUT HIM IN A COMA.
-NO.
BUT YOU CAN SAVE HIM.
IN A WAY, I WILL.
BY SAVING MYSELF.
PHLOX SAYS
THERE'S ALMOST NO CHANCE
THAT THE ENZYME WILL WORK.
MY LIFE IS AT STAKE!
ANY CHANCE IS WORTH TAKING!
BUT AT WHAT COST?!
IT'LL TAKE A DAY
TO SYNTHESIZE THE ENZYME.
BY THAT TIME YOUR NEURAL TISSUE
WON'T BE COMPATIBLE
WITH TRIP'S ANYMORE.
HE'LL DIE!
I KNOW.
I CAN'T LET THAT HAPPEN.
SO, WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
DRAG ME DOWN TO SICK BAY,
FORCE ME ONTO A BIOBED
AT GUNPOINT?
IF YOU TRULY HAVE
ALL OF TRIP'S MEMORIES...
...YOU KNOW THE ANSWER TO THAT.
I DON'T HAVE TO TELL YOU
WHAT'S AT STAKE.
I MUST COMPLETE THIS MISSION.
AND TO DO THAT, I NEED TRIP.
TRIP!
I'LL TAKE WHATEVER STEPS
NECESSARY TO SAVE HIM.
-EVEN IF IT MEANS KILLING ME?
-EVEN IF IT MEANS KILLING YOU.
YOU'RE NOT A MURDERER.
DON'T MAKE ME ONE.
I WAS WONDERING IF THERE'S
ANYTHING I COULD STILL DO.
MAYBE THERE'S A PANEL
I COULD INSTALL OR SOMETHING.
I'VE GOT A FEW HOURS TO KILL
BEFORE MY OPERATION.
YOU WISH TO SPEND YOUR
LAST HOURS IN ENGINEERING?
WHY NOT?
THE TWO THINGS I CARE ABOUT MOST
ARE IN THIS ROOM.
IF YOU'D LIKE, THE A-3
INJECTOR PORT NEEDS REPLACING.
I'LL GET RIGHT ON IT.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
SOMEONE'S REROUTED
THE LAUNCH BAY CONTROLS.
WE'RE SHUT OUT.
ARCHER TO THE LAUNCH BAY.
COME IN.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN, I'M READING
ONE PERSON IN THERE.
I WAS ALL READY TO DO IT.
WHAT STOPPED YOU?
WHERE THE HELL WAS I GONNA GO?
WE'RE NOWHERE NEAR
ANY HABITABLE PLANET.
DIDN'T REALLY WANT TO
SPEND THE REST OF MY LIFE
FLOATING AROUND IN A SHUTTLEPOD.
WHICH DOESN'T EVEN
HAVE ANY TOILET FACILITIES.
CAN YOU IMAGINE A LOUSIER WAY
TO SPEND YOUR OLD AGE,
COOPED UP IN THAT THING?
PEEING IN A BOTTLE?
ACTUALLY, I CAN IMAGINE
A WORSE FATE.
WHAT WOULD THAT BE?
BEING STUCK IN THERE
WITH MALCOLM.
[ LAUGHS ]
DAMN.
THIS IS A SCREWED-UP SITUATION.
I CAN'T ARGUE WITH YOU THERE.
A LIFETIME IN EIGHT DAYS.
IT'S NOT THAT
I'M SCARED OF DYING.
IT'S JUST THAT I CAN'T IMAGINE
NOT BEING HERE TOMORROW.
YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT REALLY STOPPED ME?
-WHAT?
-MY SISTER.
AND SHE WAS MY SISTER
AS MUCH AS TRIP'S.
I BELIEVE THAT.
I DON'T WANT WHAT HAPPENED TO
HER TO HAPPEN TO ANYONE ELSE.
THAT'S WHY I GAVE THE ORDER
TO CREATE YOU.
DO ME A FAVOR WHEN THIS IS OVER.
IF COMMANDER TUCKER DECIDES
TO DO ANY MORE MODIFICATIONS
TO THE ENGINES...
...TELL HIM TO WATCH HIS ASS.
[ BEEPS ]
YES?
WE'RE READY FOR YOU.
ON MY WAY.
MAY I COME IN?
I JUST WANTED TO SAY...
...HOW MUCH YOUR ABSENCE
WILL AFFECT THE CREW...
...HOW MUCH IT WILL AFFECT ME.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
ALL IN ALL, I GUESS I'VE HAD
A PRETTY GOOD LIFE.
I COULDN'T HAVE ASKED FOR
A BETTER GOING-AWAY PRESENT.
I'M SORRY I DOUBTED YOU, DOC.
-NO NEED TO APOLOGIZE.
-YES, THERE IS.
YOU SEE, I DON'T JUST REMEMBER
TRIP'S CHILDHOOD.
I REMEMBER MINE.
YOU MADE A DAMN GOOD FATHER.
YOU WERE A DAMN GOOD SON.
YOU SAID TO ME ONCE
THAT COMMANDING A STARSHIP
WAS WHAT YOU WERE MEANT TO DO.
I GUESS THIS IS
WHAT I WAS MEANT TO DO.
GOOD LUCK, CAPTAIN.
THANKS.
YOU OWE ME ONE.
[ CLICKS ]
WE WILL NEVER FORGET
WHAT HE DID FOR US
AND FOR THE SHIP
HE LOVED SO MUCH.
WE WILL GO FORWARD
WITH RENEWED DETERMINATION
TO COMPLETE THIS MISSION
SO THAT HIS SACRIFICE
WON'T JUST HAVE BEEN
FOR THE PEOPLE ON THIS SHIP
BUT FOR ALL THE CITIZENS
OF EARTH.