( telephone rings )
Hello?
MALE XINDI: Have you made your selection?
Y-yeah, yeah. It's all set.
Just like we discussed.
We'll be expecting you.
And, um... And the money?
Same as last time, right?
MALE XINDI: The same.
Be careful with the sedative.
You nearly killed the last one.
MAN: 100 milligrams.
Don't worry. I'll get it right.
MALE XINDI: We'll be expecting you.
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And I will see my dream
Come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
Hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna
Change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart
Will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength
Of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend
Or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got, I've got ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
You looking for a date, honey?
Maybe with your friend.
You don't know what you're missing.
He's all yours.
Ooh!
What can I do for you, sweetheart?
Hey, I know you. From this morning.
You brought me the apple juice.
-What?
-At the clinic.
Oh, yeah. Now I remember.
( chuckles )
Small world, huh?
-Want me to get in?
-Sure. Yeah.
-Bye, girl.
-Have fun.
There's a nice place to park
right in the neighborhood.
Turn left at the next light.
Georgia Tandy. "O" negative.
How the hell would you remember that?
Uh, it's another two blocks.
If that's drugs, I am not interested.
What you got in there?
Come here.
( muffled screaming )
( screaming stops )
There you go. There you go.
It's OK.
They said they won't hurt you.
( buzzes )
MALE XINDI: Yes?
Loomis.
( buzzes )
There you go. Nice and comfy.
( Porthos barks )
Good boy.
Cheese?
( barks )
This is your last piece.
It's OK.
How have you been, Jonathan?
It's about time you showed up.
Our mission has changed quite a bit
since the last time I saw you,
but I suppose you're aware of it.
I am.
Maybe you could fill in
a few of the blanks for me.
The Xindi weapon would be
a good place to start.
We don't know any more than you do.
I thought you and your colleagues
were supposed to be
keeping an eye on the timeline.
You're from the 30th century.
Hasn't all this happened already?
History doesn't mention anything
about a conflict between humans and Xindi.
How could that be?
The events that are taking place
are the result of temporal incursions.
They are not supposed to be happening.
-But they are happening.
-Yes, they are.
But the outcome hasn't reached us yet.
It takes a while for changes
to ripple through the timeline.
The time traveler...
the man the Suliban work for...
What about him?
He's the one who told us
about the weapon being built.
-Should I believe him?
-You have no reason not to.
You said I'm supposed to play
some crucial part in history.
Does this have something to do with it?
I wish I could say that it does,
but I don't know.
I told you,
none of this was supposed to happen.
You're not being very helpful!
Why are you here?
We've detected three Xindi
where they're not supposed to be.
This expanse is filled with Xindi.
I'm not talking about the expanse.
I'm talking about Detroit, Michigan.
150 years ago.
( door chimes )
Sorry to get you up,
but this couldn't wait.
Come in.
I just had a visit from Daniels.
I think all your doubts about time travel
are about to go out the window.
Meaning?
Daniels and his team
have discovered three reptilians on Earth.
In the early 21st century.
He wants to send us back
to find out what they're doing.
Us?
He told me I could bring one person,
no more.
If Daniels is the time traveler
he claims to be,
why doesn't he find out for himself?
It took him a long while
to get permission to interact with me.
There are clearances.
He said it would take too much time.
I would think he would have
all the time in the world.
He said the three Xindi traveled
to Earth from our century.
They've been there for two months.
They're not sightseeing, T'Pol.
We have to find out what they're up to.
How are we supposed to accomplish this?
He wants us to meet him in
the command center at 0800 tomorrow.
Come on, boy.
Check the database.
Find something to wear
that won't stand out in 2004.
( door opens )
Last time Daniels
sent you to another century,
you had one hell of a time getting back.
He gave me this.
Said he'd return us
whenever we signaled him.
These are temporal tags.
We can use them to bring back anything
that doesn't belong there.
If anybody asks where you went,
what should I tell them?
With two shuttlepods in the bay,
it'll be hard to explain.
I'm sure you'll think of something.
-Try to stay out of trouble.
-You too.
Here's the duty roster.
We just traveled 90 light-years
back to Earth.
And 150 years into the past.
Forgive me if I'm not entirely convinced.
You will be.
Come on.
( beeping )
This one has a motion-activated
security system.
( beeping )
This one too.
( chirping )
We're in.
This apparatus...
It appears to have been designed
to incapacitate the vehicle.
( beeping, chirping )
( barking )
( door unlocks )
MAN ON RADIO: Sunday! Sunday! Sunday!
At the tri-city speedway!
An all-star lineup of all your
favorite monster mayhem...
( radio turns off )
Have you ever operated a vehicle
from this period?
I can pilot a starship.
"R," "N," "D," 2, 3, 4...
I suggest you begin with 2.
Foot controls.
( beeping )
I don't believe you've activated
your external lighting.
-What year is that map from?
-2002.
It was the closest I could find
in the Starfleet database.
The layout shouldn't have
changed a lot in two years.
Turn starboard on 24th street.
If that thing has a scanning radius
of three kilometers,
how far are we gonna have
to drive to cover the entire city?
I've created a search grid that requires
a journey of approximately 80 kilometers.
But it's probable we'll find them
before we complete it.
What's that icon?
It's a gasoline pump. We need to get fuel.
-Where?
-Where isn't the problem.
We're going to need money. U.S. currency.
That's going to be difficult
at this time of night.
Not necessarily.
( beeping )
( teller machine whirs, beeps )
People used to go to jail for this.
We'll return what we don't use.
( indistinct conversations )
( doorbell rings )
-Yeah?
-Are you Lawrence Strode?
-Who are you?
-I'm from the blood bank.
We had a screw-up this afternoon.
We gave you the wrong papers to sign.
I'm not giving the money back.
No, no, no, no, no.
They don't want the money back.
In fact, they're gonna pay you again.
25 bucks.
They just need you
to sign the right papers.
-Did you bring them?
-No, they wouldn't let me.
You got to do it
in front of the supervisor.
You know, the fat broad who paid you?
They sent me to drive you down.
-It's 11:00 at night.
-Yeah, I know.
They want to send your blood work out
first thing in the morning,
and they can't do it
without the right paperwork.
You want the 25 bucks or not?
( indistinct talking on television )
( chain unlatches )
Is this gonna take long?
I don't want to miss Conan.
Were they aware at this time
that Earth's supply of fossil fuel
was nearing depletion?
They had been for 30 years.
But it wasn't until 2061
that they finally--
( beeping )
One kilometer, straight ahead.
Second structure from the left.
Three Xindi bio-signs.
Any humans?
Five. In another part of the building.
ARCHER:
This doesn't look very residential.
Set your phase pistol to kill.
When the reptilians boarded Enterprise,
stun had no effect.
See what you can find out.
I'll look over there.
( communicator beeps )
Go ahead.
There's a neutronic power source
coming from the first floor.
I found a gate
with an electric locking mechanism.
We shouldn't have a problem.
Do you see the vehicle?
I see it.
( buzzes )
MALE XINDI: Yes?
-Loomis.
-( buzzes )
MALE XINDI: Did you disinfect your hands?
I insert IVs all day. I told you that.
If there are any infections here,
it won't be because of me.
You forget something?
We've decided to compensate you
for the final three patients
in one payment.
That's not what we agreed.
You said I'd get paid for each one.
Bring us the last two blood types,
and you will be compensated.
We should wait a while.
A few more days at least.
There was something on the news.
Cops are starting to get complaints
that people have gone missing.
We can't wait a few more days.
We need the last two.
Look, as soon as they figure out
that all these people here
have been to the clinic,
it won't take a rocket scientist
to point the finger at me.
Then I suggest
you finish your work quickly.
Look, I don't know
what you guys are up to,
and I don't want to know.
It's not my business.
But the cops don't take kindly
to people who help terrorists.
I got to be real careful.
We will double your fee
for the final three.
But the last two must be here by tomorrow.
Double?
Tomorrow?
Yeah. All right.
I'll have them here by tomorrow.
Here he comes.
Ninth floor.
280 pounds.
William Myers.
Second floor.
( knock on door )
( grunts, gasps )
And the man in the wheelchair?
Why were you bringing him
to an abandoned factory
in the middle of the night?
I swear, I don't know
what you're talking about.
What's this?
Oh.
Oh, I took that from the clinic.
I work at the blood bank on Porter Street.
Check with them. They'll tell you.
I've been there for over a year.
-Why would you take it?
-Make a few extra bucks.
There's plenty of people on the street
looking for that stuff.
Really?
Why would anyone on the street
be interested in acquiring methohexital?
You make it a habit
of climbing out your window
when someone knocks on the door?
I don't like cops.
Tell us about your friends
on Carpenter Street.
I've never been to Carpenter Street.
You were there an hour ago
with a man in a wheelchair.
Now tell me who's inside that factory.
I told you,
I don't know what you're talking about.
I think it's time you find me a lawyer.
Untie him.
You heard him.
Untie me.
( Loomis grunts )
That's better.
( groans )
( panting )
I didn't feel right doing that
with you tied up.
Carpenter Street.
-You're not allowed to hit me.
-Untie him again.
No, no, no, no!
Wait a minute!
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
I don't know who he is, I swear to god.
A doctor, maybe.
Says he's working on a vaccine,
experimental.
He says he doesn't have approval
or something like that.
So he needed me to bring him people.
Does it seem logical to you
that legitimate medical research
is being conducted
in an abandoned factory?
I thought about that.
Just tonight I thought maybe
he's some kind of a terrorist.
But I swear, if I knew that for a fact,
I never would have agreed to help him.
In one individual, we've managed to find
the worst qualities of this era.
Greed. Violence. Moral corruption.
But he said
he wasn't going to hurt anybody.
I just saw them an hour ago.
They were all OK.
-How many?
-Five.
No, no, six.
The wheelchair guy was number six.
How did this "doctor" find you?
I told you I work at the blood bank.
He wanted someone from every blood type.
Eight blood types, eight people.
He figured I had access
to that kind of information.
Did he also figure
that you'd have no compunctions
about abducting people?
What's he paying you?
$5,000 apiece. Double for the last three.
Is that what human life is worth
in the 21st century?
I told you, he said he wasn't
going to hurt any of them.
What does he look like?
He only calls me on the phone.
I saw him a couple of times,
but he stays in the shadows.
You know, he's kind of tall.
That's all I can tell you.
Why don't you let me go?
I swear to you, I will never do it again.
You are going to do it again.
That is, if you have any hope
of staying out of prison.
-What are you talking about?
-These two files...
"AB" positive and "B" negative.
-They're the final two?
-Yeah.
Well...
Then you're looking at your next victim.
A healthy male with "B" negative blood.
If you think you're gonna
be in there a long time,
-we should get something to eat first.
-Be quiet.
Come on, I'm not...
I'm not talking about anything fancy.
A burger?
A taco?
There's a drive-through
less than a mile from here.
Cops have to eat, don't they?
What is the matter with you two? I'll pay.
I told you to be quiet.
What side of the street is it on?
FEMALE: Welcome to Burgerland.
How may I serve you today?
I'll have the double superbeef,
no lettuce.
One double superbeef without lettuce,
please.
FEMALE: You can make that a triple
for only 40 cents extra.
Do it.
A double will be fine.
FEMALE: Would you like
to make that a combo?
Yeah. Fries and a medium root beer.
FEMALE: Will there be anything else today?
A hamburger, ketchup only.
FEMALE: You can make that a double
for only 40 cents extra.
No, thank you.
Would you like to make that a combo?
No. No combo.
FEMALE: Will there be anything else today?
Does the fiesta salad
contain animal products?
FEMALE: No, but we can add three strips
of bacon for only 75 cents more.
Nothing for me, thank you.
-ARCHER: You sure?
-Quite.
You guys don't mind, do you? I'm starving.
You know, it'd make it a lot easier
if you'd untie my hands.
It's not like I'm going anywhere.
Do the best you can.
Uh-oh. I told you.
Let me get that for you.
Oh, boy.
You're a veggie. I forgot.
Why don't you take a fry?
They're probably OK.
Have it your way.
( whispers ) They'll come in to take
fresh blood samples every hour.
They readminister the sedative
every six hours.
I recommend you do whatever
you're gonna do before then.
( door opens )
Number seven.
Which one is it?
"B"... "B" negative.
You'll have AB positive
by tomorrow night, I swear.
Make certain I do.
Engage the engine and proceed
to the second location.
Nice ray gun.
Am I supposed to believe that thing's
for real?
Drive.
Ten grand apiece for the last three,
and I'm not gonna see a penny of it.
Don't speak until
we're out of visual range.
MALE XINDI:
15 milliliters from the new arrival.
LOOMIS: You catch these guys
and I get immunity, right?
We're not talking about
copping to a lesser charge.
T'POL: When my associate returns,
we'll discuss the details.
Hey, I'm taking a big chance here, OK?
If your associate doesn't catch them,
they're gonna come looking for me, OK?
You two better keep your word.
You've been abducting people for money,
and you're questioning our honesty?
Sit back.
Relax. I'm just getting a smoke.
What are you doing?
I don't know about you, honey,
but I'm a little tense, know what I mean?
Extinguish that now.
If you want some air, open your window.
Now.
( whirring )
( communicator beeps )
( keys jingling )
Stay exactly where you are.
T'Pol.
ARCHER: They brought
a bio-reactor with them.
They're synthesizing
some kind of viral agent.
Rajiin warned us about a bio-weapon.
This could be it.
Why would they travel back through time?
ARCHER: Daniels said they might be
hiding from someone.
The past seems like
a pretty good place to hide.
We've got to keep them
from getting it back to our time.
Are you in a position
to disable all three of them?
I don't know.
I was thinking about trying
to take out the bio-reactor,
but I could end up spreading
whatever's in there across half the city.
They must have some kind of
temporal beacon.
If you can destroy it,
they'll have no way of getting back.
I've got to find it first.
Modify your scanner
to a delta band frequency.
That should...
( yells )
They've gone out the west door.
They could be headed for the street.
They have the virus.
-T'Pol.
-Yes, Captain.
They're in the west alleyway,
north of the main building.
-I could use some help.
-Acknowledged.
Drive.
Trouble?
Pull over and stop. Here.
Give you all that fancy equipment,
and what good does it do you?
Lower your window.
I knew your partner's plan wouldn't work.
Be quiet.
They're coming.
-( honking )
-Stop!
( beeps )
Come on.
ARCHER: He's trying to release the toxin.
We've eliminated his only means
of returning to his own century.
Perhaps he has no other choice.
ARCHER: If he's trying
to destroy humanity,
he's not gonna be able to do it with that.
They only modified the virus
for six blood types.
If they can infect
three-quarters of Earth's population,
it's unlikely humans would pose
a threat to them in the future.
Let's hope he can't see in the dark.
Keep laying down fire.
( guns firing )
-Don't move a muscle.
-( hisses )
Drop it.
Why a second weapon?
Where were you going to take it?
We won't allow you to destroy us.
Your species is doomed.
Let's go.
Problem, sir?
It's done.
Sir?
-Archer to Lieutenant Reed.
-MALCOLM: Go ahead.
Get a team down
to the command center on the double.
Aye, sir.
Wait here for Malcolm.
Have everything brought to cargo bay 2.
I've got to get this to Phlox.
-What's going on?
-Come with me.
( sirens wailing )
-Get out of the car!
-He's on something.
Get out of the car!
Keep your hands where we can see them.
Come on. Come on.
What's going on?
Hey, hey, hey, hey. I didn't do anything.
OFFICER: We got a tip says you did.
You're just lucky
all six of them are still alive.
Those two cops that came to my place,
they offered me a deal.
That's the only reason I helped them.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Get him out of here.
Those creatures... The lizard people...
They're around here somewhere.
You got to find them.
No problem. We'll get right on that.
Be careful. Be careful. They got ray guns.
Yeah, ray guns. Got it. Watch your head.