PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
STATUS.
WE'RE GETTING REPORTS
OF ANOMALIES ON ALL DECKS.
IF WE CONTINUE,
THERE'S A GOOD CHANCE
THIS SHIP
IS GONNA GET TORN APART.
[ GROANS ]
THINK WHAT YOU'RE
ASKING ME TO DO --
BUILD A WEAPON
TO DESTROY AN ENTIRE WORLD.
WE DO NOT HAVE ENOUGH
INFORMATION ABOUT THE HUMANS.
THAT CAN BE REMEDIED.
THEY'RE LOCKING ONTO
THE STARBOARD DOCKING PORT.
I'M READING 23 INTRUDERS
ON DECKS "C," "D," AND "E."
WE'RE PREPARING
TO TEST THE WEAPON
ON AN UNINHABITED PLANET,
BUT WE'RE GOING TO NEED
ANOTHER SHIPMENT OF KEMOCITE.
I'LL CONTACT GRALIK.
GRALIK.
I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS FOR YOU.
I WANT TO KNOW WHERE
THEY'RE SHIPPING THIS KEMOCITE.
IT COULD LEAD US TO THE WEAPON.
THERE'S NO DOUBT
ABOUT IT, CAPTAIN.
THIS ISOTOPE WAS USED IN
THE WEAPON THAT ATTACKED EARTH.
YOU OFFERED TO HELP US.
ARE YOU STILL WILLING?
IF YOU'RE PREPARED TO TRUST ME.
WE'VE MODIFIED
THE RADIOLYTIC SIGNATURE.
IF YOU CAN GET IT ON BOARD THEIR
SHIP, I'LL BE ABLE TO TRACK IT.
DEGRA'S GOING TO DISCOVER
THAT YOU SABOTAGED HIS KEMOCITE.
YOU SHOULD JUST BE CONCERNED
WITH FINDING THIS WEAPON.
THEY BROKE ORBIT
FIVE MINUTES AGO, CAPTAIN.
ARE YOU PICKING UP
THE TRACKING SIGNAL?
LOUD AND CLEAR.
[ BEEPING ]
YES?
COMMANDER SHRAN, WOULD YOU
COME TO THE BRIDGE?
STATUS.
WE'VE LOST THE WARP TRAIL.
CONTINUE SCANNING.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR,
LIEUTENANT.
IT SHOULDN'T BE
THAT DIFFICULT TO FIND.
COMMANDER.
WE'VE BEEN SEARCHING FOR WEEKS.
AND WE'LL CONTINUE SEARCHING
UNTIL WE'VE ACCOMPLISHED
OUR MISSION.
OR UNTIL WE'RE DESTROYED?
YOU'VE SEEN
WHAT THIS PLACE IS LIKE.
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
THEY'VE SURVIVED?
WE HAVE OUR ORDERS.
WE SHOULD HEAD BACK TO ANDORIA
WHILE WE'RE STILL ABLE.
YOU SOUND LIKE YOU'RE AFRAID
OF THIS EXPANSE, LIEUTENANT.
I'D EXPECT THAT FROM A VULCAN,
NOT A MEMBER
OF THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
CONTINUE SCANNING.
DON'T UNDER THESE PINK SKINS,
LIEUTENANT.
THEY'RE STILL OUT THERE.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
-WHERE ARE THE OTHERS?
-DELAYED.
I SAID THE MATTER WAS URGENT.
TYPICAL HUMANOID ARROGANCE.
YOU EXPECT US TO COME SCURRYING
WHENEVER IT SUITS YOU.
I'M SORRY TO INCONVENIENCE YOU.
BUT I'M SURE YOU'LL FIND
THE JOURNEY WORTH THE EFFORT.
THE WEAPON IS READY?
NOT QUITE.
THEN WHY ARE YOU WASTING
OUR TIME?
THE NEW PROTOTYPE
HAS BEEN COMPLETED.
WE'VE SCHEDULED A TEST.
-WHEN?
-THREE DAYS.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO VIEW THE TEST
REMOTELY FROM THIS CHAMBER.
IF EVERYTHING GOES AS PLANNED,
WE SHOULD BE READY TO DEPLOY
THE FINAL VERSION IN A MONTH.
MAYBE SOONER.
AND THE HUMAN THREAT
WILL FINALLY BE ELIMINATED.
I HOPE YOU FIND THAT
WORTH YOUR TIME.
THE SIGNAL WAS SO WEAK
I WASN'T EVEN SURE
THAT IT WAS THERE AT FIRST.
-BUT YOU ARE NOW?
-YES, SIR.
THE ISOTOPIC SIGNATURE
MATCHES THE KEMOCITE
THAT YOU PLANTED
ON THE XINDI SHIP.
SET A COURSE.
TELL TRIP I WANT EVERYTHING
HE CAN GIVE ME FROM THE ENGINES.
CAPTAIN, AS YOU KNOW,
ENSIGN SATO AND I
HAVE BEEN WORKING
TO RECONSTRUCT OUR DATABASE.
AND?
WE'VE MANAGED TO DIG ABOUT 30%
OF THE LOST DATA
OUT OF
THE REDUNDANT MEMORY CORE.
ENOUGH TO BEGIN PIECING TOGETHER
A MAP OF THE SPATIAL ANOMALIES.
THE SIGNAL LIES JUST BEYOND
A DENSE FIELD OF THEM.
-HERE.
-HOW LONG TO GO AROUND IT?
THE FIELD IS MASSIVE.
17 DAYS AT WARP 5.
ALERT THE CREW.
IT'S GONNA GET ROUGH.
-TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE.
-GO AHEAD.
I'VE GOT THE WARP REACTOR
BUTTONED UP.
WE'RE AS READY AS WE'LL EVER BE.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
T'POL?
I'VE CHARTED
THE LARGEST ANOMALIES,
BUT THE FIELD
IS EXTREMELY DENSE.
WE MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO AVOID ALL OF THEM.
DO YOUR BEST.
TRAVIS.
TAKE US IN.
ONE-HALF IMPULSE.
AYE, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
COME TO, BEARING 2-7-5 MARK 8.
-[ BEEPING ]
-HARD TO PORT!
WE JUST GRAZED IT.
NO DAMAGE.
JUST HOW ACCURATE
IS THIS MAP OF YOURS?
CONSIDERING I ONLY HAVE 30%
OF OUR DATABASE TO WORK WITH...
[ BEEPING ]
THERE'S AN ANOMALY FORMING
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
IT'S EXPANDING.
EXPANDING?
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS BEFORE.
THEY'RE MERGING,
BUILDING ON ONE ANOTHER.
WHICH WAY, SUBCOMMANDER?
IT'S GROWING TOO RAPIDLY.
EMERGENCY POWER TO HULL PLATING!
BRACE FOR IMPACT!
AAH!
WE'RE LOSING HULL INTEGRITY.
ATMOSPHERE IS VENTING
ON "D" DECK.
COME ABOUT.
GET US OUT OF HERE.
THE HELM'S NOT RESPONDING.
WE'VE BEEN COMPLETELY ENVELOPED.
MAIN POWER IS GOING DOWN.
SIR, I'M PICKING UP SOMETHING
OUT THERE.
I THINK IT'S A SHIP.
-CAN YOU IDENTIFY IT?
-THERE'S TOO MUCH DISTORTION.
A TRACTOR BEAM'S LOCKED ONTO US.
WE'VE BEEN PULLED OUT.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY'RE HAILING US.
I GUESS WE OWE SOMEONE
A THANK YOU.
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
LOOK AT THE TROUBLE
YOU'VE GOTTEN
YOUR PINK SKIN INTO THIS TIME.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU'RE BRAVER THAN I IMAGINED.
I WOULDN'T TRY TO TRAVERSE
AN ANOMALY FIELD
IN A SHIP THIS FRAGILE.
YOU DON'T SEEM TO BE HAVING
ANY TROUBLE.
WE'VE DISCOVERED A FEW TRICKS
TO DEAL WITH THEM.
HOW DID YOU LOCATE US?
WE HAVE A RECORD
OF YOUR WARP SIGNATURE
FROM OUR LAST ENCOUNTER.
OUR SHIPS ARE CONSIDERABLY
FASTER THAN ENTERPRISE.
IT WASN'T DIFFICULT
TO CATCH UP WITH YOU.
THAT EXPLAINS HOW YOU GOT HERE.
IT DOESN'T EXPLAIN WHY.
YOUR WORLD
WAS BRUTALLY ATTACKED.
THE IMPERIAL GUARD THOUGHT YOU'D
BE GRATEFUL TO HAVE AN ALLY,
CONSIDERING NO ONE ELSE
CAME RUSHING TO YOUR AID.
AND HOW DID THE IMPERIAL GUARD
KNOW EARTH HAD BEEN ATTACKED?
SEVEN MILLION KILLED?
NOT EXACTLY A STATE SECRET.
ESPECIALLY IF YOU'RE
MONITORING COMMUNICATIONS
BETWEEN STARFLEET
AND THE VULCAN HIGH COMMAND.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR UNIFORM,
SUBCOMMANDER?
NOT THAT I DON'T FIND
YOUR NEW LOOK BECOMING, BUT...
...IT'S NOT EXACTLY REGULATION,
IS IT?
I RESIGNED MY COMMISSION.
YES, I BELIEVE I HEARD
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
YOUR WORLD IS IN JEOPARDY,
AND WHERE ARE YOUR FRIENDS,
THE VULCANS?
WHERE IS THEIR MIGHTY FLEET?
THEY COULDN'T EVEN SPARE
ONE OFFICER.
SHE WAS FORCED TO ABANDON HER
CAREER TO REMAIN ON YOUR SHIP.
A REMARKABLY SELFLESS ACT.
FOR A VULCAN.
BUT WE'VE COME TO YOUR AID.
WE'VE COME INTO THE EXPANSE
WHEN THEY REFUSED.
WE'RE HERE TO HELP YOU.
IF YOU DON'T
WANT OUR ASSISTANCE,
THEN WE'LL LEAVE YOU TO DEAL
WITH THE XINDI ON YOUR OWN.
JUST LIKE THE VULCANS HAVE DONE.
TARGETING SENSORS ARE DOWN,
HULL PLATING.
WE'RE DAMN LUCKY THE TORPEDOES
WERE ALL IN SAFE MODE.
IF ONE OF THEM HAD DETONATED...
PHASE CANNONS?
THEY HAVEN'T EVEN GOT ENOUGH
POWER TO LIGHT A CAMPFIRE.
HOW LONG TO FIX THEM?
I COULDN'T EVEN GUESS WITHOUT
A CHANCE TO SORT THIS OUT.
COMMANDER SHRAN OFFERED TO
SEND HIS TACTICAL OFFICER OVER
TO HELP.
WE'D BE GIVING THEM ACCESS
TO CRITICAL SYSTEMS, SIR.
THE KEMOCITE SIGNAL
HOSHI PICKED UP
COULD LEAD US
TO THE XINDI WEAPON.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
OUR DEFENSES.
I DON'T LIKE THE IDEA OF HAVING
THE ANDORIANS DOWN HERE
ANY MORE THAN YOU DO.
BUT WE COULD USE THEIR HELP.
AYE, SIR.
THE ANDORIAN SHUTTLE
HAS DOCKED.
GOOD.
LET'S PUT THEM TO WORK.
I RECOMMEND WE ASSIGN A SECURITY
DETAIL TO EACH REPAIR CREW.
YOU'VE BEEN TALKING
TO LIEUTENANT REED?
THEY'RE HERE TO HELP, T'POL.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN
WE SHOULDN'T EXERCISE CAUTION.
I'M NOT GONNA ASK THEM TO WORK
WITH GUNS AT THEIR HEADS
JUST BECAUSE
YOU DON'T LIKE THEM.
I NEITHER LIKE
NOR DISLIKE ANDORIANS.
I'VE SIMPLY HAD A GREAT DEAL
OF EXPERIENCE WITH THEM.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
BUT WHATEVER PROBLEMS
EXIST BETWEEN VULCAN AND ANDORIA
DON'T INVOLVE US.
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
WE WEREN'T ALWAYS
SO ANTAGONISTIC, CAPTAIN.
IN FACT, DESPITE THEIR
HEIGHTENED EMOTIONS,
OUR FIRST CONTACT WITH ANDORIANS
SEEMED PROMISING.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THEY WERE DUPLICITOUS.
THEY ONLY HONORED AGREEMENTS
THAT DIDN'T CONFLICT
WITH THEIR INTERESTS.
IS THAT YOUR ASSESSMENT,
OR THE HIGH COMMAND'S?
CONSIDERING THE IMPORTANCE
OF THIS MISSION,
I FEEL COMPELLED
TO POINT OUT
THAT THEY'VE PROVEN
UNTRUSTWORTHY IN THE PAST.
I DON'T TRUST THEM EITHER,
T'POL.
BUT BASED ON MY EXPERIENCE,
I THINK I CAN TRUST
COMMANDER SHRAN.
COFFEE. BLACK.
NO TEA?
YEAH, NO CRUMPETS, EITHER.
THANK YOU.
I NEED ALL THE CAFFEINE
I CAN GET.
WHAT'S THE SITUATION
IN ENGINEERING?
BAD.
-THE ARMORY?
-WORSE.
WHICH ONE OF YOU IS REED?
I'M LIEUTENANT REED.
I ASSUMED I'D FIND YOU
IN THE ARMORY,
NOT RELAXING HERE.
[ SNIFFS ]
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S COFFEE.
AND JUST FOR THE RECORD,
I HAVEN'T LEFT THE ARMORY
FOR SO MUCH AS A BATHROOM BREAK
IN NEARLY 12 HOURS.
AND YOU ARE?
LIEUTENANT TALAS OF
THE IMPERIAL WARSHIP KUMARI.
THIS IS COMMANDER TUCKER,
OUR CHIEF ENGINEER.
PLEASURE.
I'VE BEEN ORDERED TO ASSIST YOU.
INDEED.
WELL, I'LL SEE IF I CAN FIND
SOMETHING FOR YOU TO DO.
I HAVE DUTIES OF MY OWN.
THE SOONER YOUR SHIP
IS REPAIRED,
THE SOONER I CAN
GET BACK TO THEM.
WELL, I'LL LET YOU TWO
GET ACQUAINTED.
I WASN'T SURE
WE'D FIND YOU ALIVE.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I'D SAY WE HAVE SOMETHING
TO CELEBRATE.
I APPRECIATE THE GESTURE, BUT WE
HAVE A LOT OF REPAIRS TO MAKE.
AND YOUR CREW IS DOING
A FINE JOB OF MAKING THEM.
HAVE A DRINK WITH ME.
YOU'VE EARNED A BRIEF RESPITE.
ANDORIAN ALE.
YOU SEEMED TO ENJOY IT
THE LAST TIME WE MET.
I TOOK THE LIBERTY OF BRINGING
A FEW EXTRA BOTTLES.
THANKS.
TO A SWIFT VICTORY.
[ EXHALES SLOWLY ]
-SO...
-[ ALE POURING ]
HOW DID YOU GET PICKED
FOR THIS ASSIGNMENT?
I VOLUNTEERED.
IT MADE SENSE.
I'VE HAD THE GREATEST AMOUNT
OF CONTACT WITH PINK--
WITH HUMANS.
AND THE LAST TIME WE MET, YOU
HELPED MY PEOPLE AVERT A WAR.
I DON'T LIKE UNPAID DEBTS.
WE KEEP DOING EACH OTHER FAVORS.
ISN'T THAT HOW ALLIANCES
ARE BORN?
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU IN AWHILE.
AS LONG AS YOU'RE HERE,
MAYBE YOU CAN GIVE ME A HAND.
TOUCH THIS TO
THE PHASE REGULATOR, THERE...
WHILE I CHECK THE POLARITY.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT BE
AVOIDING ME.
THREE NEUROPRESSURE SESSIONS
A WEEK IS HARDLY AVOIDING YOU.
THE CAPTAIN ASKED FOR AN UPDATE
ON YOUR REPAIRS.
WELL, THREE OF THE INJECTORS
ARE BURNED OUT.
THE RESTRICTER COILS
ARE COMPLETELY FRIED.
HOW LONG UNTIL WE HAVE WARP?
I WOULD SAY AT LEAST TWO DAYS,
BUT, UH, THE BLUE GUYS
REALLY KNOW THEIR STUFF.
WE SHOULD BE UP AND RUNNING
IN ABOUT 12 HOURS.
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
NO.
KEEP ME INFORMED
OF YOUR PROGRESS.
HAND ME THE MICROSPANNER,
PLEASE.
I'VE BROUGHT SOME EQUIPMENT
THAT SHOULD ALIGN THOSE RELAYS
MUCH MORE PRECISELY.
THE SPANNER
WILL DO THE JOB NICELY.
IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND?
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
I CAN GET YOU?
SOME COFFEE, PERHAPS?
THAT'D BE LOVELY.
SINCE YOU CLEARLY DON'T NEED MY
HELP, I'LL RETURN TO MY SHIP.
THANK YOU FOR THE HOSPITALITY.
GIVE MY REGARDS
TO COMMANDER SHRAN.
FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH,
LIEUTENANT,
I'M NOT HERE
TO STEAL YOUR SECRETS.
IT WOULD HARDLY
BE WORTH THE EFFORT.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
THE LAST TIME
I SAW WEAPONS LIKE THESE
WAS DURING
MY EARLY TACTICAL TRAINING.
I'M SORRY I WASTED YOUR TIME
ON OUR PRIMITIVE SYSTEMS.
NOT AT ALL.
I FOUND IT NOSTALGIC.
JUST BE CAREFUL
WHEN YOU RECONNECT THAT
TO YOUR POWER GRID.
YOU DIDN'T RESET
THE E.P.S. SYNCHRONIZER.
YOU MAY SINGE YOUR EYEBROWS
WHEN YOU BRING IT BACK ONLINE.
LIEUTENANT TALAS.
I APOLOGIZE IF I'VE BEEN RUDE.
WHY DON'T I GET US BOTH
A CUP OF COFFEE
AND WE CAN ALIGN
THESE RELAYS TOGETHER?
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
DECEMBER 6, 2153.
WITH SOME ASSISTANCE
FROM THE ANDORIANS,
WE'VE MANAGED TO STEER CLEAR
OF ANOMALIES.
200 MILLION KILOMETERS.
CLOSE ENOUGH, TRAVIS.
WE DON'T WANT TO
GIVE OURSELVES AWAY.
AYE, SIR.
IT'S A G-TYPE STAR SYSTEM.
SIX PLANETS WITH OVER 100 MOONS.
ANY BIO-SIGNS?
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL OF DEBRIS
IN THE SYSTEM.
I CAN'T TELL FROM THIS RANGE.
OUR SENSORS ARE MORE
SOPHISTICATED THAN YOURS.
WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO SCAN THE SYSTEM
WITHOUT BETRAYING
OUR PRESENCE.
IF I MAY?
-THIS IS COMMANDER SHRAN.
-GO AHEAD.
TRANSFER OUR LONG-RANGE
SENSOR DATA TO ENTERPRISE.
YES, COMMANDER.
IT'S COMING IN.
FOUR VESSELS.
ALL XINDI.
MANY OF THE MOONS SHOW EVIDENCE
OF EXTENSIVE
WEAPONS BOMBARDMENT.
WHY ATTACK
AN UNINHABITED SYSTEM?
I DON'T THINK
THEY ATTACKED ANYONE.
IT'S BIKINI ATOLL.
WHAT?
WHEN MY SPECIES WAS DEVELOPING
PRIMITIVE NUCLEAR WEAPONS,
THEY NEEDED PLACES TO TEST THEM.
ONE WAS A REMOTE ISLAND
CALLED BIKINI ATOLL.
SO YOU BELIEVE THIS IS
SOME KIND OF PROVING GROUND?
IT'S POSSIBLE.
IF THEY ARE GETTING READY
TO TEST THEIR WEAPON,
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
I WOULDN'T RECOMMEND
A FRONTAL ASSAULT.
YOUR WEAPONS ARE DAMAGED.
CRITICAL SYSTEMS ARE DOWN
ALL OVER YOUR SHIP
AND YOU'RE OUTNUMBERED 4-TO-1.
I THOUGHT IT WAS 4-TO-2.
EVEN OUR COMBINED FORCES
DON'T STAND A CHANCE AGAINST
THAT KIND OF FIREPOWER.
I'M NOT READY TO RISK MY SHIP
WHEN WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF THE XINDI WEAPON IS HERE.
I AGREE.
WE NEED TO GET A CLOSER LOOK.
WHAT DO YOU PROPOSE WE DO?
FLY UP TO THEM AND ASK THEM
WHAT THEY'RE DOING?
ENSIGN.
COMMANDER.
I'LL TAKE HIM FROM HERE.
MR. TUCKER, HOW ARE
YOUR REPAIRS COMING ALONG?
PRETTY WELL,
THANKS TO YOUR PEOPLE.
BUT I WAS WONDERING
IF I COULD ASK A FAVOR.
I'M TOLD
YOUR ANTIMATTER INJECTORS USE
VARIABLE-COMPRESSION NOZZLES.
TOLD BY WHOM?
THAT'S RATHER SENSITIVE
INFORMATION.
I DON'T WANT TO GET
ANYONE IN TROUBLE,
BUT ONE OF THOSE INJECTORS WOULD
WORK WONDERS FOR OUR ENGINES.
I IMAGINE IT WOULD.
I DON'T KNOW, COMMANDER.
THAT'S A SOPHISTICATED
PIECE OF TECHNOLOGY.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALLIES HERE.
THAT REMAINS TO BE SEEN.
[ BEEPING ]
YOU HAVE MY CONDOLENCES
OVER THE ATTACK ON YOUR WORLD.
THANKS.
I UNDERSTAND
YOUR SISTER WAS KILLED.
CAPTAIN ARCHER TOLD ME.
WELL, LOTS OF PEOPLE
LOST FAMILY.
NO GREAT VICTORY
COMES WITHOUT SACRIFICE.
THE DISPUTE BETWEEN MY PEOPLE
AND THE VULCANS
HASN'T BEEN BLOODLESS.
BORDER SKIRMISHES WERE COMMON
A FEW DECADES AGO.
THEY'D VIOLATE OUR TERRITORY,
WE'D RETALIATE.
I WAS STILL IN SCHOOL
WHEN MY OLDER BROTHER
JOINED THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
HE WAS ASSIGNED TO
A FORWARD SURVEILLANCE UNIT.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY YOU SEEK
VENGEANCE AGAINST THESE XINDI.
I'D LOVE TO GET MY HANDS
ON WHOEVER ORDERED THAT ATTACK.
BUT THAT'S NOT WHY WE'RE HERE.
YOU HAVE NO DESIRE
TO MAKE THESE PEOPLE PAY
FOR THE DEATH OF YOUR SISTER?
I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
THEY DON'T GET THE CHANCE
TO FINISH WHAT THEY STARTED.
SO ANY HELP YOU CAN GIVE US...
I'LL HAVE THAT ANTIMATTER
INJECTOR DELIVERED TO YOU.
I APPRECIATE IT.
DEGRA, WHAT'S THE DELAY?
STAND BY.
WE HAVE BEEN STANDING BY
FOR NEARLY AN HOUR!
WE'RE CONFIRMING
FINAL POWER READINGS.
I WOULDN'T WANT YOU TO BE
DISAPPOINTED WITH THE RESULTS.
DEPLOY THE WEAPON.
INITIATE FIRING PROTOCOLS.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
A SHIP JUST ENTERED THE SYSTEM.
WE CAN'T IDENTIFY IT.
ABORT THE TEST.
RETURN THE WEAPON
TO THE LAUNCH PLATFORM.
-DEGRA, REPORT.
-STAND BY.
ACTIVATE ALL DEFENSE SYSTEMS.
CONTACT THE OTHER VESSELS AND
HAVE THEM INTERCEPT THAT SHIP.
DEGRA.
WE ARE SECURING THE WEAPON.
I'LL RESUME CONTACT WHEN I CAN.
WE'RE RECEIVING A TRANSMISSION
FROM THE SHIP.
ALLOW ME TO INTRODUCE MYSELF.
MY NAME IS SHRAN.
OF THE ANDORIAN
MINING CONSORTIUM.
YOU'VE ENTERED
RESTRICTED SPACE.
LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
RESTRICTED?
I HAD NO IDEA.
WE DON'T WANT TO CAUSE
ANY TROUBLE.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR
A RARE ELEMENT.
ARCHERITE.
WE PICKED UP
SOME PROMISING READINGS
COMING FROM YOUR SYSTEM.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
TURN YOUR SHIP AROUND
AND LEAVE.
OF COURSE, OF COURSE.
BUT YOU DON'T MIND
IF WE FINISH OUR SCANS?
ARCHERITE IS
EXTREMELY VALUABLE TO US.
EVEN A FEW KILOS
WILL PAY OUR EXPENSES
FOR THE NEXT 10 CYCLES.
THEY'RE SCANNING OUR SHIPS.
WE'RE NOT TRYING
TO VIOLATE YOUR PRIVACY.
OUR SENSORS ARE OMNIDIRECTIONAL.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE CONCERNED ABOUT.
DEACTIVATE YOUR SCANS AND LEAVE,
OR WE'LL DESTROY YOU!
THERE'S NO NEED FOR THREATS.
WE'LL LEAVE.
BUT IF THIS SYSTEM
DOES CONTAIN ARCHERITE,
YOU JUST MISSED OUT
YOUR OPPORTUNITY
TO COLLECT
A GENEROUS PERCENTAGE!
STOP THE SCAN.
TAKE US OUT OF THE SYSTEM,
BUT NOT TOO QUICKLY.
THE ANDORIAN MINING CONSORTIUM
RUNS FROM NO ONE.
IT'S EMITTING HIGH LEVELS
OF RADIATION.
COULD BE ANYTHING.
POWER GENERATOR OF SOME KIND,
FUSION REACTOR.
IT HAS THE SAME
QUANTUM SIGNATURE
AS THE WEAPON
THAT ATTACKED EARTH.
WHAT'S THE STATUS
OF OUR REPAIRS?
IMPULSE AND WARP ENGINES
ARE NOMINAL.
HULL PLATING IS AT 82%.
WEAPONS?
MR. REED REPORTS THE ANOMALY
CAUSED MORE DAMAGE THAN
HE ORIGINALLY ESTIMATED.
HOW LONG?
HE ISN'T CERTAIN.
PERHAPS TWO DAYS.
IF THEY ARE HERE
TO TEST THAT THING,
WE MAY NOT HAVE TWO DAYS.
WHY THE URGENCY?
THIS CAN'T BE THE FINAL VERSION
OF THE WEAPON.
T'POL'S ANALYSIS SHOWS
IT ISN'T POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO DESTROY AN ENTIRE PLANET.
LET THEM RUN THEIR TESTS.
WHY DESTROY THIS PROTOTYPE
WHEN WE CAN SEE IT IN USE,
GAUGE ITS DESTRUCTIVE POWER?
I DON'T INTEND TO DESTROY IT.
IF WE COULD GET OUR HANDS
ON THIS WEAPON,
STARFLEET MIGHT BE ABLE
TO FIGURE OUT A DEFENSE.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE IT.
THE PHASE COUPLERS ARE CHARGING.
AH, ALL WE HAVE LEFT
IS TO RESET THE EMITTERS.
WHAT'S THE FREQUENCY?
I'LL DO IT.
YOU DON'T TRUST ME.
NO OFFENSE,
BUT WHEN IT COMES TO
OUR WEAPONS FREQUENCIES,
I WOULDN'T TRUST MY OWN MOTHER.
IS YOUR MOTHER CONSIDERED
A SECURITY RISK?
IT'S JUST AN EXPRESSION.
AN ODD ONE.
MY MOTHER'S SECURITY CLEARANCE
IS HIGHER THAN MINE.
REALLY?
SHE COMMANDED
AN IMPERIAL INFANTRY UNIT.
YOU COME FROM A MILITARY FAMILY?
FOUR GENERATIONS.
HUH.
THREE.
ON MY FATHER'S SIDE.
HE MUST BE DISAPPOINTED IN YOU.
WHAT?
BETRAYING YOUR FAMILY TRADITION
BY SERVING
ON A SHIP OF...EXPLORATION.
ACTUALLY, WE HAVEN'T DONE MUCH
EXPLORING FOR QUITE AWHILE.
BUT SINCE YOU ASK,
HE WASN'T VERY PLEASED.
THE ROYAL NAVY WAS HIS LIFE.
PERHAPS HE'D FEEL DIFFERENTLY
IF HE SAW YOU NOW...
...FIGHTING FOR THE SURVIVAL
OF YOUR RACE.
I'M SURE HE WOULD.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL DONE.
I'LL POWER IT UP, AND...
WE'LL SEE WHERE WE STAND.
[ BEEPING ]
-REPORT.
-THEY'VE LAUNCHED THE PROTOTYPE.
CAN WE GET A CLOSER LOOK?
-THIS IS SHRAN.
-YES, COMMANDER.
TRANSFER OUR SENSOR TELEMETRY
TO ENTERPRISE.
ARE THESE THE SATISFYING RESULTS
YOU PROMISED?
THE DEVICE WAS BUILDING
TO AN OVERLOAD.
WE WERE FORCED TO SHUT IT DOWN.
WHY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
I NEED TIME TO ANALYZE THE DATA.
TIME?
WE HAVE GIVEN YOU
MORE THAN ENOUGH TIME.
WE WERE PROMISED A WEAPON
TO DESTROY THE HUMANS
IN ONE STROKE,
NOT PECK AWAY AT THEM,
BIT BY BIT.
THAT MOON
WAS NEARLY SPLIT IN TWO.
CLEARLY, PROGRESS HAS BEEN MADE.
NOT ENOUGH.
EVERY FAILURE PUTS US AT RISK.
DEGRA, CAN THE PROBLEM
BE RECTIFIED?
ONCE I'VE RECOVERED THE DEVICE,
I'LL HAVE MORE INFORMATION.
WE HOPE SO.
THE OUTPUT WAS MUCH GREATER THAN
THE PROBE THAT ATTACKED EARTH,
BUT STILL I DON'T BELIEVE
THE DEVICE
REACHED ITS MAXIMUM YIELD.
WE DETECTED POWER FLUCTUATIONS.
IT APPEARS IT WAS BUILDING
TOWARD AN OVERLOAD.
ARE YOU SAYING
THIS WAS A FAILURE?
A SPECTACULAR ONE, BUT YES.
[ CHUCKLES ]
GRALIK.
AN ARBOREAL XINDI WE MET
AT A FACILITY THAT MANUFACTURED
ONE OF THE COMPONENTS
FOR THE WEAPON.
HE PROMISED TO HELP US.
LOOKS LIKE HE KEPT HIS WORD.
WHY HAVEN'T THEY RETRIEVED IT?
IT'S STILL EMITTING
HIGH LEVELS OF RADIATION.
HOW LONG UNTIL IT'S SAFE ENOUGH
TO GET CLOSE?
SIX HOURS, AT LEAST.
WE'VE GOT TO GET TO IT
BEFORE THEY DO.
WHAT IF WE SHIELD
THE LAUNCH BAY,
EVACUATE ALL
THE ADJACENT COMPARTMENTS?
COULD WE BRING IT ABOARD
ANY SOONER?
OUR SHIELDING WOULDN'T BE
SUFFICIENT TO PROTECT THE CREW.
USE MY SHIP.
OUR FORCE FIELD
WILL CONTAIN THE RADIATION.
WE'LL SECURE THE DEVICE
IN OUR CARGO BAY
UNTIL IT'S SAFE TO TRANSFER
TO ENTERPRISE.
THAT'S A GENEROUS OFFER.
BUT WHAT ARE WE SUPPOSED TO DO,
CHEER YOU ON?
IT'S FOUR AGAINST TWO.
REMEMBER?
THIS WOULD BE A JOINT VENTURE.
ARCHER TO LIEUTENANT REED.
REED HERE, SIR.
WHAT'S THE STATUS ON WEAPONS?
TORPEDOES ARE BACK ONLINE.
AND THANKS TO LIEUTENANT TALAS,
WE SHOULD HAVE PHASE CANNONS
WITHIN THE HOUR.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED THEM.
ARCHER OUT.
I WISH WE HAD MORE TIME.
YOU'RE ONLY GOING TO GET
94% EFFICIENCY
FROM THE PHASE CANNONS.
I'VE NEVER GOTTEN THEM
ABOVE 93%.
IF YOU EVER DECIDE TO LEAVE
THE IMPERIAL GUARD,
STARFLEET COULD
CERTAINLY USE YOU.
AND IF YOU GET TIRED
OF EXPLORING,
YOU'D DO WELL
IN THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
I APPRECIATE YOUR OFFER, SHRAN.
WE ACCEPT.
I'LL RETURN TO MY SHIP.
I'M GOING WITH YOU.
I PLAN TO BE THERE WHEN
YOU BRING THE WEAPON ABOARD.
THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY.
WE'LL KEEP YOU INFORMED.
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
IF SOMETHING GOES WRONG --
THE KUMARI IS A WARSHIP
WITH A BATTLE-TESTED CREW.
THEY'RE CAPABLE
OF PERFORMING THEIR DUTIES
WITHOUT YOU LOOKING OVER
THEIR SHOULDERS.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THIS BEING
A JOINT VENTURE?
WE'LL RENDER
WHATEVER ASSISTANCE WE CAN.
BUT MY CREW WON'T TAKE ORDERS
FROM YOU.
THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE TO.
THE IMPERIAL GUARD DOESN'T SERVE
AT YOUR LEISURE, PINKSKIN!
THIS IS MY MISSION!
AND YOU'D PASS UP
YOUR BEST CHANCE FOR SUCCESS
OVER A MATTER OF PRIDE?!
THIS ISN'T ABOUT PRIDE.
THE XINDI KILLED SEVEN MILLION
HUMANS, NOT ANDORIANS.
I WON'T PUT
THE FATE OF MY PEOPLE
IN THE HANDS OF
THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
NOW, WE COULD USE YOUR HELP.
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT HAPPY
WITH ME CALLING THE SHOTS,
THEN WE'LL GO IT ALONE.
I'VE SEEN THE SCANS
YOU TRANSMITTED, COMMANDER.
IMPRESSIVE.
ARCHER'S SCIENCE OFFICER
BELIEVES THE WEAPON IS UNSTABLE.
IT NEARLY OVERLOADED.
THE VULCAN?
I HAVE NO REASON
TO DOUBT HER ASSESSMENT.
SHE SEEMS...COMPETENT.
WE'LL REVIEW HER DATA.
PROCEED AS PLANNED.
GENERAL, THE HUMANS
MAY YET BECOME VALUABLE ALLIES.
IF YOUR MISSION IS SUCCESSFUL,
WE WON'T NEED
AN ALLIANCE WITH THEM.
OR ANYONE.
WHY SQUANDER THE OPPORTUNITY?
IS THIS MISSION WORTH
MAKING ENEMIES OF THEM?
IT'S NOT UP TO YOU TO DETERMINE
THE VALUE OF THIS MISSION,
COMMANDER.
I TRUST YOUR REGARD
FOR THIS PINKSKIN
WON'T CAUSE YOU TO FORGET THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHY ARE YOU ACCESSING
THE SENSORS?
THEY WEREN'T DAMAGED.
NOT BY THE ANOMALY.
WITH ALL THE BYPASSES
WE'VE BEEN RUNNING,
WE OBVIOUSLY COULD HAVE CREATED
SOME ADDITIONAL PROBLEMS.
YOU'RE JUST BEING THOROUGH.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO BE
IN A BATTLE WITH THE XINDI
AND SUDDENLY FIND YOURSELF
FLYING BLIND.
SO ANYTHING WE NEED
TO WORRY ABOUT?
YOUR LATERAL ARRAY
WAS OUT OF ALIGNMENT.
I CORRECTED IT.
ALL OTHER SYSTEMS
ARE FUNCTIONING PROPERLY.
I'D TAKE THIS SHIP
INTO COMBAT MYSELF.
EVEN WITH OUR PRIMITIVE WEAPONS?
IT'S NOT THE WEAPON,
IT'S THE SOLDIER WHO WIELDS IT.
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
A SHIP.
-THE ANDORIANS?
-NO.
BIO-SIGNS ARE HUMAN.
WE HAVE TO KEEP THEM
AWAY FROM THE WEAPON.
TWO XINDI SHIPS APPROACHING.
TACTICAL ALERT.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS, ENSIGN.
AYE.
HAIL THE CAPTAIN.
[ BEEPS ]
THE TWO REPTILIAN SHIPS
ARE MOVING TOWARD US.
THE OTHER VESSELS
ARE HOLDING POSITION.
-TRY TO KEEP THEM BUSY.
-ACKNOWLEDGED.
I AWAIT YOUR ORDERS.
LET'S GO GET IT.
CHARGE WEAPONS AND SET A COURSE.
[ BEEPING ]
ANOTHER VESSEL.
IT'S THE ANDORIAN SHIP.
THEY'RE HEADING FOR THE WEAPON.
THEY'RE WORKING TOGETHER.
GET OUR SHIPS BACK HERE NOW!
HULL PLATING'S HOLDING.
RETURN FIRE.
TARGET THEIR ENGINES.
THEY'RE BREAKING OFF.
THEY'RE HEADING BACK
INTO THE SYSTEM.
PURSUIT COURSE, ENSIGN.
CONTINUE FIRING ALL WEAPONS.
WE HAVE IT.
TAKE US OUT OF THE SYSTEM.
MAXIMUM SPEED.
-ARE THEY FOLLOWING?
-NO.
THE HUMAN VESSEL DISABLED
MAIN PROPULSION ON BOTH SHIPS.
WHAT ABOUT ENTERPRISE?
THEY'VE GONE TO WARP.
NO APPARENT DAMAGE.
CONTACT T'POL.
HAVE HER MEET US
AT THE RENDEZVOUS POINT.
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
INFORM THE IMPERIAL GUARD
WE HAVE THE WEAPON.
SET A COURSE FOR ANDORIA.
MAXIMUM WARP.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M AFRAID WE WON'T BE TAKING
ORDERS FROM YOU ANY LONGER.
NOW I SEE WHY YOU GENEROUSLY
OFFERED TO LET US USE YOUR SHIP.
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
I WAS ORDERED
TO RETRIEVE THE WEAPON
BY WHATEVER MEANS NECESSARY.
I'M STARTING TO THINK THE
VULCANS MAY BE RIGHT ABOUT YOU.
THE VULCANS ARE THE REASON
WE'RE DOING THIS!
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?!
FOR 200 YEARS, ALL THAT'S
KEPT THEM FROM INVADING ANDORIA
IS THE THREAT OF
MASSIVE RETALIATION.
WITH A WEAPON OF THIS
MAGNITUDE AT OUR DISPOSAL,
THEY WOULDN'T DARE ATTACK US.
YOU'RE PUTTING EARTH AT RISK
BECAUSE OF A BORDER DISPUTE
WITH THE VULCANS?
WE DISRUPTED THE XINDI TEST,
TOOK THEIR WEAPON!
WE MAY HAVE HELPED
SAVE YOUR WORLD!
I GUESS I'M NOT FAMILIAR WITH
THE ANDORIAN CONCEPT OF HELP!
I DON'T NEED TO JUSTIFY
MY ACTIONS TO YOU, PINKSKIN.
I SWORE AN OATH
TO THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
MY LOYALTY LIES WITH THEM.
MY CREW WON'T LET YOU TAKE
THE WEAPON WITHOUT A FIGHT.
YOUR SHIP ISN'T FAST ENOUGH
TO CATCH US.
YOU'LL HAVE TO SLOW DOWN TO PASS
BACK THROUGH THE ANOMALY FIELD.
I ANTICIPATED THAT.
WHEN TALAS WAS
WORKING ON ENTERPRISE,
SHE DISRUPTED
THE MAIN SENSOR ARRAY.
THEY MAY BE ABLE
TO CATCH UP TO US,
BUT THEY'LL HAVE NO WAY
TO FIND US.
YOU LIKE TO TALK ABOUT
REPAYING DEBTS.
I'VE OWED YOU THAT
FOR A LONG TIME.
TAKE THE CAPTAIN
TO AN ESCAPE POD.
DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL ALERT ENTERPRISE
WHERE TO FIND YOU.
WE DISABLED MAIN POWER
ON BOTH REPTILIAN SHIPS.
THE OTHER VESSELS
AREN'T PURSUING US.
-WHAT ABOUT OUR SENSORS?
-BACK ONLINE.
YOU WERE RIGHT, SIR.
IF I HADN'T BEEN WATCHING
THAT ANDORIAN OFFICER,
IT MIGHT HAVE TAKEN WEEKS
TO FIND OUT
WHERE SHE SABOTAGED THE ARRAY.
THEIR SHIP?
IT'S APPROACHING
THE ANOMALY FIELD.
THEY REDUCED SPEED.
WE'LL INTERCEPT THEM
IN 14 MINUTES.
WE'VE BEGUN
EXAMINING THE WEAPON.
EXCELLENT WORK.
I'LL SEE THAT YOU RECEIVE
A COMMENDATION.
WITH RESPECT, GENERAL,
I'D PREFER YOU DIDN'T.
TRANSMIT YOUR ANALYSIS
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
[ BEEPING ]
COMMANDER SHRAN.
WHAT IS IT?
ENTERPRISE IS APPROACHING.
WHERE ARE THEY?
80,000 KILOMETERS.
THEY'RE HAILING US.
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
GLAD TO SEE
YOU MADE IT BACK SAFELY.
HOW DID YOU FIND US?
YOU DON'T THINK I'D LET
YOUR PEOPLE WORK ON MY SHIP
WITHOUT APPROPRIATE
SUPERVISION.
GIVE US THE WEAPON.
I RESPECT YOUR PERSEVERANCE.
BUT YOU DON'T ACTUALLY THINK
YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO TAKE IT FROM US.
NO.
I THINK YOU'RE GOING TO
GIVE IT TO US.
WILLINGLY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I SHOULD HAVE WARNED YOU.
DON'T DRINK TOO MUCH OF THAT
ANDORIAN ALE IN ONE SITTING.
YOU TOSSED ME OVERBOARD BEFORE
I HAD A CHANCE TO THANK YOU
FOR LETTING US ACCESS
YOUR SENSOR TELEMETRY.
WHEN THE XINDI
TESTED THE WEAPON,
WE WERE ABLE TO INTERCEPT
THEIR ACTIVATION CODES.
GIVE IT TO US.
OR WE'LL DETONATE IT
IN YOUR CARGO BAY.
YOU'LL LOSE YOUR PRIZE.
I'D RATHER DO THAT THAN LET YOU
TAKE IT BACK TO ANDORIA.
WHY?
WE'RE NOT YOUR ENEMY.
I CAN'T TAKE THE CHANCE
THAT YOU'D USE IT
AGAINST THE VULCANS.
WHAT HAVE THE VULCANS DONE
TO DESERVE YOUR LOYALTY?
YOU SAID YOU CAME
TO HELP US, SHRAN.
YOU CAN STILL MAKE GOOD
ON YOUR OFFER.
I'M SORRY, PINKSKIN.
YOU'RE NOT GIVING ME
ANY CHOICE.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
TAKE US INTO THE ANOMALY FIELD.
T'POL.
[ BEEPING ]
SHRAN TO CARGO HOLD 3.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
THE FIRING MATRIX HAS ACTIVATED.
I BELIEVE
THE DEVICE IS ARMING ITSELF.
-SHUT IT DOWN!
-WE'RE TRYING, COMMANDER.
I'D GET RID OF IT
WHILE YOU STILL CAN.
REPORT!
THEY HAVE LESS THAN 30 SECONDS.
SHRAN...
20 SECONDS.
CLEAR THE HOLD!
PREPARE TO OPEN THE BAY DOORS.
-SIX SECONDS.
-LET'S GET MOVING.
ALREADY ON IT, SIR.
[ WHIRRING ]
NO DAMAGE, SIR.
THE ANDORIANS?
THEY WERE MUCH CLOSER
THAN WE WERE.
THEIR HULL'S INTACT,
BUT THERE'S SIGNIFICANT DAMAGE
TO THEIR ENGINES
AND POWER SYSTEMS.
OPEN A CHANNEL TO SHRAN.
ASK HIM IF HE REQUIRES
OUR ASSISTANCE.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
COMMANDER SHRAN GRACIOUSLY
DECLINED OUR OFFER OF HELP.
THE LAST WE SAW OF THEM,
THEY WERE LIMPING AWAY
ON AUXILIARY POWER.
YOU HAVE SOMETHING?
JUST BEFORE WE WENT TO WARP,
WE RECEIVED A TRANSMISSION
FROM THE ANDORIAN SHIP.
IT WASN'T ON ONE OF
THEIR NORMAL COM FREQUENCIES.
IT WAS ENCRYPTED TO LOOK LIKE
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE.
LET'S SEE IT.
APPARENTLY THEY HAD TIME
TO TAKE SOME DETAILED SCANS
WHILE IT WAS ABOARD THEIR SHIP.
JUDGING FROM THE CLANDESTINE
NATURE OF THE TRANSMISSION,
I'D GUESS THAT WHOEVER SENT THIS
DIDN'T WANT TO BE DISCOVERED.
GET IT TO STARFLEET COMMAND
RIGHT AWAY.
WHY DON'T YOU AND TRIP
JOIN ME FOR DINNER TONIGHT?
I HAVE SOME ANDORIAN ALE
YOU MIGHT LIKE TO TRY.