PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
WHOEVER BUILT THESE SPHERES
MAY HAVE DONE IT
TO CREATE THE EXPANSE.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE
WANT TO CREATE
A WEB OF CRIPPLING ANOMALIES?
[ GRUNTS ]
WE BELIEVE THAT IT IS
THROUGH PRAYER AND MEDITATION
THAT THE MAKERS BECOME MANIFEST.
THE MAKERS?
THE CREATOR OF THE SPHERES.
THE QUICKER YOU FOLKS
FIND THESE XINDI,
THE QUICKER WE CAN GET TO WORK.
MILITARY ASSAULT COMMAND.
CAPTAIN ARCHER WANTED THE BEST.
I'VE SEEN MEN LIKE HAYES
ALL MY LIFE.
LIEUTENANT?
THAT HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH WHO KNOWS ENTERPRISE
INSIDE AND OUT.
IT HAD TO DO
WITH WHO THE MAJOR THINKS
IS MORE CAPABLE
OF CARRYING OUT THIS RESCUE.
IT'S ONLY BEEN A DAY
SINCE WE WERE ENEMIES.
GIVING YOU THE COORDINATES
TO A CLASSIFIED INSTALLATION
IS DIFFICULT.
THEY'RE COMING IN.
THE COORDINATES MATCH
THE LOCATION
OF ONE OF THE RED GIANTS.
UGH!
DR. PHLOX SAYS
WE HAVE TO PREPARE
FOR THE POSSIBILITY
THAT TRIP WON'T SURVIVE.
WHEN IMPLANTED WITH DNA
FROM ANOTHER SPECIES,
IT EXACTLY REPLICATES
THAT SPECIES' LIFECYCLE.
IT BECOMES A CLONE.
YOU AND TRIP USED TO SPEND
A LOT OF TIME HERE TOGETHER.
I WAS INSTRUCTING HIM
IN THE PRACTICE
OF VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE.
HE WAS REALLY STARTING TO
ENJOY THOSE SESSIONS WITH YOU.
WHAT'S DRIVING ME CRAZY
IS I DON'T KNOW
IF THESE FEELINGS ARE MINE...
OR HIS.
MALCOLM CAN BE A TOUGH MAN
TO GET TO KNOW,
I'LL GRANT YOU THAT.
HE LIKES TO KEEP TO HIMSELF.
THIS FEEL OKAY?
MM-HMM.
BUT, YOU SPEND ENOUGH TIME
AROUND HIM,
YOU COME TO REALIZE
THERE'S NO ONE
YOU'D RATHER HAVE
WATCHING YOUR BACK.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU WEREN'T TICKLISH.
I DIDN'T USED TO BE.
MAYBE I'M DOING THIS WRONG.
MAYBE WE SHOULD TRY
ANOTHER POSITION.
POSTURE? SURE.
TAKE A SEAT.
I JUST GET THE FEELING
THAT WHENEVER LIEUTENANT REED
LOOKS AT ONE OF US,
HE SEES THE ENEMY.
I DON'T THINK MALCOLM THINKS
OF MACOS AS THE ENEMY.
COMPETITION, MAYBE.
RELAX.
THIS IS ONE OF
THE FIRST PRESSURE POINTS
T'POL WORKED ON.
HELPED ME GET THROUGH
MANY A NIGHT.
FEELS GREAT.
TOO BAD THIS CAN'T BE
A PART OF OUR TRAINING ROUTINE.
YOU SHOULD BRING IT UP
WITH HAYES.
HIS TRAINING REGIMEN HASN'T
CHANGED SINCE I JOINED UP.
MAJOR HAYES LIKES CONSISTENCY.
YEAH, SO DOES MALCOLM.
HE TOLD ME THAT WHILE HE WAS
IN STARFLEET TRAINING,
HE ATE THE EXACT
SAME THREE MEALS EVERY DAY
FOR A YEAR.
THEY'RE DEFINITELY CUT
FROM THE SAME CLOTH
[ LAUGHS ]
MAYBE THAT'S WHY
THEY GET ALONG SO WELL.
HOW'S IT FEELING?
STILL GREAT.
THERE.
I FEEL LIKE I'VE JUST HAD
12 HOURS' SLEEP.
WELL, I GUESS I DID IT RIGHT.
WELL.
THAT WAS UNEXPECTED.
NOTHING WRONG
WITH UNEXPECTED.
NO.
UM, WITH A LITTLE WARNING.
CONSIDER THAT A LITTLE WARNING
FOR NEXT TIME
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
DECEMBER 27TH, 2153.
USING THE COORDINATES
WE GOT FROM DEGRA,
WE'RE EN ROUTE TO THE LOCATION
OF THE RED GIANT STAR
AND, WITH ANY LUCK,
THE XINDI WEAPON.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
YOU WANTED TO SEE ME, SIR?
I HAD A CONVERSATION WITH
MAJOR HAYES THIS MORNING.
HE WANTS TO PUT
YOUR SECURITY TEAM
AND ALL THE SENIOR OFFICERS
THROUGH A SERIES
OF TRAINING DRILLS.
WE RUN DRILLS TWICE A WEEK.
SENIOR OFFICERS
ARE FREE TO ATTEND.
THESE WOULD BE DIFFERENT.
THEY'D BE CONDUCTED BY
MAJOR HAYES AND THE MACOS.
SIR?
WE'RE HEADING
INTO A HOSTILE SITUATION.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE GONNA
FACE WHEN WE GET THERE.
MY PEOPLE ARE READY, SIR.
THE MACOS' TACTICS
AND TECHNOLOGY
ARE TWO, THREE YEARS
BEYOND STARFLEET'S.
WHY NOT LET THEM PASS ON
SOME OF THAT EXPERTISE?
YOU DON'T AGREE.
UH...THE MACOS' EXPERTISE
COMES FROM SIMULATED COMBAT,
ALL CONDUCTED ON EARTH.
ON THE OTHER HAND, WE'VE FOUGHT
NUMEROUS ALIEN SPECIES
ON MANY DIFFERENT WORLDS.
IF ANYTHING,
WE SHOULD BE GIVING THE MACOS
THE BENEFIT OF OUR EXPERIENCE.
HAYES AND HIS MEN
HAVE GONE UP AGAINST
A FEW ALIENS ON THIS MISSION,
INCLUDING THE XINDI.
THEY'VE HANDLED THEMSELVES
PRETTY WELL.
I'D LIKE YOU TO COORDINATE
THE TRAINING SESSIONS
WITH THE MAJOR.
AYE, SIR.
AH, I APPRECIATE YOUR
STOPPING BY SO QUICKLY.
WHAT DID YOU WANT TO ASK ME?
ARE YOU ACQUAINTED WITH
CORPORAL AMANDA COLE?
[ SQUEAKING ]
SHE'S ONE OF THE MACOS.
SHE WAS IN THIS MORNING
WITH A MILD HEADACHE,
SAYS SHE'S BEEN EXPERIENCING IT
FOR A WEEK NOW.
EVERY TEST I RAN
CAME BACK NEGATIVE.
FRANKLY, I WAS MYSTIFIED
UNTIL SHE MENTIONED
SHE WAS RECEIVING
VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE
FROM COMMANDER TUCKER.
YOU BELIEVE IT'S
CAUSING HER HEADACHES?
WELL, I WANTED TO ASK YOU.
NEUROPRESSURE'S A HIGHLY
SPECIALIZED DISCIPLINE.
COMMANDER TUCKER'S ONLY BEEN
RECEIVING IT
FOR A COUPLE OF MONTHS.
I THOUGHT IT WAS POSSIBLE
THAT HE MIGHT HAVE MISAPPLIED
ONE OF ITS TECHNIQUES.
-IT'S POSSIBLE.
-HMM.
WELL, I'VE ALREADY SPOKEN
TO CORPORAL COLE
ABOUT USING CAUTION,
BUT I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU MIGHT HAVE A WORD
WITH COMMANDER TUCKER,
PERHAPS DURING YOUR, UH,
NEXT SESSION WITH HIM.
GLADLY.
AH.
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
YES.
IF THERE'S NOTHING ELSE.
OH, TH-THERE IS, UH...
ONE OTHER THING.
IF YOU FIND TIME,
PERHAPS YOU COULD SCHEDULE
A NEUROPRESSURE SESSION
WITH CORPORAL COLE, HMM,
MAYBE UNDO SOME OF
COMMANDER TUCKER'S WORK.
OKAY, TUESDAY, WEDNESDAY,
AND FRIDAY.
HOW DOES 0800 SOUND?
I PREFER TO TRAIN
IN THE EVENINGS.
ANY REASON?
YOU GET A BETTER WORKOUT.
MUSCLES ARE LOOSER,
REACTION TIME'S QUICKER.
HOW ABOUT TUESDAYS
AND FRIDAYS IN THE MORNING,
WEDNESDAYS IN THE EVENING?
HOW ABOUT TUESDAYS
AND FRIDAYS IN THE EVENINGS,
AND WEDNESDAY IN THE MORNING?
YOU'RE NOT MAKING THIS
VERY EASY.
I'M NOT TRYING
TO MAKE IT DIFFICULT.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
I THINK THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT YOU'RE TRYING TO DO.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT?!
IS THAT WHAT YOU CALL
CIRCUMVENTING MY AUTHORITY?
I WASN'T AWARE I'D DONE THAT.
AND WHAT DID YOU THINK
YOU WERE DOING
WHEN YOU WENT TO THE CAPTAIN
WITH THIS PROPOSAL?
IF I'D COME TO YOU FIRST,
YOU'D HAVE TURNED ME DOWN FLAT.
YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT. BUT
THE DECISION WAS MINE TO MAKE.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO DEPRIVE YOU
OF THE OPPORTUNITY.
I THINK THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT YOU MEANT TO DO.
WHATEVER YOU MIGHT THINK, SIR,
MY ONLY CONCERN
IS THE SUCCESSFUL OUTCOME
OF THIS MISSION.
AS IS MINE.
TUESDAYS AND FRIDAYS,
IN THE EVENINGS.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT, CAPTAIN.
IT'S LIKE THE STARS
KEEP SHIFTING POSITIONS.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THERE. THEY JUST DID IT AGAIN.
MAYBE IT'S ONE
OF THE NAVIGATIONAL SENSORS.
I'VE ALREADY RUN
TWO DIAGNOSTICS.
I CAN'T FIND ANYTHING WRONG.
I THINK I HAVE THE CAUSE --
AN UNUSUALLY STRONG
GRAVIMETRIC DISTURBANCE
APPROXIMATELY
THREE LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
LET'S GO TAKE A LOOK.
IT APPEARS TO BE A CONVERGENCE
OF SPATIAL ANOMALIES.
IT'S MORE THAN 700 MILLION
KILOMETERS IN DIAMETER.
CAPTAIN, I'M PICKING UP
AN INTERMITTENT SIGNAL.
VERY FAINT.
AN OBJECT, APPROXIMATELY
FIVE METERS IN LENGTH.
LET'S SEE IT.
IT'S JUST A FEW HUNDRED METERS
FROM THE EDGE.
I'M READING ONE BIO-SIGN.
HUMANOID.
COULD BE AN ESCAPE POD.
ARE THERE ANY OTHER SHIPS
IN THE VICINITY?
NONE.
THE BIO-SIGNS ARE VERY ERRATIC.
BRING THE GRAPPLER ONLINE.
TRY AGAIN.
I'LL SEE IF I CAN COMPENSATE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
TRAVIS?
[ COUGHS ]
WE'RE LOSING SYSTEMS
ALL OVER THE SHIP.
HELM'S NOT RESPONDING.
THERE ARE RISING LEVELS
OF AMMONIUM SULFIDE
IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
COMMANDER TUCKER.
THE HELM'S NOT RESPONDING.
WE NEED FULL REVERSE RIGHT AWAY.
I'M ON IT.
HELM'S BACK ONLINE.
GET US OUT OF HERE.
LOVE TO.
WE'RE READY TO OPEN THE HATCH.
HE'S SUFFERING FROM A FORM
OF RAPID CELLULAR DEGENERATION.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN STOP IT?
I DON'T KNOW YET.
I'VE MANAGED TO REVIVE HIM, BUT
HE'S IN A FAIR AMOUNT OF PAIN.
I'M CAPTAIN ARCHER.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO BRING ME HERE.
WE WERE TRYING
TO SAVE YOUR LIFE.
I DIDN'T ASK FOR YOUR HELP.
RETURN ME TO MY SHIP.
YOUR VESSEL HAS
MINIMAL LIFE SUPPORT.
YOU WOULDN'T LAST TOO LONG
IF WE TOOK YOU BACK.
THAT'S NONE OF YOUR CONCERN.
WHAT WAS THAT POD
DESIGNED TO DO?
I'M NOT ANSWERING
ANY OF YOUR QUESTIONS.
YOU'RE DYING.
WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING WE CAN
FOR YOU, BUT --
TAKE ME BACK TO MY SHIP!
[ GROANING ]
HE MAY BE GOING INTO SHOCK.
HOW'S IT COMING?
GOOD, SIR.
WE'RE ADJUSTING
THE NAV SENSORS
TO COMPENSATE FOR
THE GRAVIMETRIC WAVES.
GET US UNDERWAY
AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
JUST NEED A DAY TO UPLOAD
AND TEST THESE CORRECTIONS.
LEARN ANYTHING?
A GREAT DEAL.
THE DISTURBANCE APPEARS
TO BE EXPANDING
AT A RATE OF
SEVERAL KILOMETERS PER SECOND,
AND ITS LOCATION
IS EXACTLY EQUIDISTANT
TO FIVE OF THE SPHERES.
DO YOU THINK THE SPHERES
HAVE SOMETHING TO DO
WITH CREATING THIS THING?
IT'S POSSIBLE.
THIS PLANET WAS ONCE
AN INHABITED WORLD.
IT WAS ENGULFED
SOME TIME AGO.
I COULDN'T FIND
ANY SIGNS OF LIFE.
MAYBE THE ALIEN WE PICKED UP
IS THE LAST SURVIVOR.
A POSSIBILITY.
I WANT YOU AND TRIP
TO TAKE A LOOK AT THE POD.
IF WE CAN'T REVIVE THE ALIEN,
IT MAY BE OUR BEST SOURCE
OF INFORMATION.
WE INCORPORATE ELEMENTS
FROM NUMEROUS DISCIPLINES.
IT'S EXTREMELY EFFECTIVE
IN HAND-TO-HAND SITUATIONS.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO NOW IS
BREAK UP INTO SPARRING PAIRS,
RUN THROUGH SOME OF THE MOVES
YOU JUST SAW.
LET'S GET STARTED.
TRY THE COMBINATION.
NICE CROSS.
EXCELLENT.
EFFECTIVE COMBINATION.
[ GRUNTS ]
YOU WERE LOOKING AT HIS HANDS
WHEN YOU SHOULD'VE BEEN
WATCHING HIS EYES.
[ CHUCKLES ]
GOOD MATCH.
ALL RIGHT, WHY DON'T WE TAKE
FIVE MINUTES --
THAT'S ALL FOR TODAY.
WE STILL HAVE
THE SHOULDER THROWS TO COVER.
SESSION IS OVER.
OKAY.
FOR NEXT TIME,
WORK ON YOUR FOREARM BLOCKS
AND THE ELBOW STRIKES.
DISMISSED.
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
THAT WAS
A SPARRING DEMONSTRATION.
IT WAS WAY OUT OF LINE.
THAT LAST THROW
WAS COMPLETELY UNNECESSARY.
HE WAS ON HIS FEET.
THAT MADE HIM FAIR GAME.
FAIR GAME?
IT'S JUST A LITTLE BLOOD, SIR.
NO ONE GOT HURT.
THESE ARE TRAINING SESSIONS,
MAJOR.
IF YOUR MEN CAN'T
UNDERSTAND THAT,
THEN I'M GONNA PUT
A STOP TO THIS RIGHT NOW.
IS THAT CLEAR?
PERFECTLY.
JOLLY GOOD.
I THINK IT'S A TRANSMITTER.
I JUST CAN'T
PINPOINT THE FREQUENCY.
DR. PHLOX HAS ASKED ME
TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
WHAT ABOUT?
CORPORAL COLE HAS BEEN
EXPERIENCING HEADACHES.
THE DOCTOR BELIEVES
THEY MIGHT BE CAUSED
BY YOUR NEUROPRESSURE SESSIONS.
SHE NEVER SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT HEADACHES.
PERHAPS SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO WORRY YOU.
WHY WOULD NEUROPRESSURE
BE THE CAUSE?
IT SHOULDN'T BE
PERFORMED BY NOVICES.
IF MISAPPLIED,
YOU COULD CAUSE NERVE DAMAGE.
I PERFORMED IT ON YOU
PLENTY OF TIMES.
UNDER MY SUPERVISION.
I SEE.
YOU WANT TO SUPERVISE ME
AND CORPORAL COLE?
I THINK IT WOULD SIMPLY BE BEST
IF YOU ENDED THE SESSIONS.
THESE ELECTRODES
WERE COLLECTING
BIOMETRIC DATA
FROM THE OCCUPANT.
AMANDA WON'T BE TOO HAPPY
ABOUT ENDING THE SESSIONS.
I'M SURE SHE WON'T.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT?
I'VE NOTICED THAT
YOU AND CORPORAL COLE
HAVE BECOME SOMEWHAT FRIENDLY.
FRIENDLY?
LAST WEEK, YOU WERE EATING
TOGETHER IN THE MESS HALL,
AND IN THE TRAINING
SESSION YESTERDAY, SHE
TOUCHED YOUR BEHIND.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
YOU'VE BEEN KEEPING
A PRETTY CLOSE EYE ON US.
YOU'RE HARD TO MISS.
LOOK, AMANDA AND I
JUST SHARE A LOT OF INTERESTS,
THAT'S ALL.
WE BOTH COME FROM FLORIDA.
THERE'S NO REASON
TO JUSTIFY YOUR BEHAVIOR.
I'M SIMPLY SUGGESTING
YOU MIGHT USE SOME DISCRETION.
DISCRETION?
IT'S NOT APPROPRIATE
FOR A SENIOR OFFICER
TO FRATERNIZE
WITH A SUBORDINATE.
SHE'S NOT STARFLEET. THERE'S
NOTHING INAPPROPRIATE ABOUT IT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
WE NEED TO GET THIS DATA
TO THE CAPTAIN IMMEDIATELY.
THERE'S NO MISTAKE.
THE POD'S HULL CONTAINS
THE EXACT COMBINATION OF ALLOYS
WE FOUND ON THE SURFACE
OF THE SPHERES.
YOU REMEMBER
THE TRIANNON CREATION MYTH?
THEY BELIEVE THAT THE SPHERES
WERE CREATED BY DIVINE BEINGS
WHO WOULD ONE DAY RETURN
TO THE CHOSEN REALM.
AND THAT THE SPHERES
WERE RESHAPING THE EXPANSE
INTO A PARADISE
FOR THE FAITHFUL.
PERHAPS TRIANNON MYTHOLOGY
HAS A BASIS IN FACT.
IT APPEARS THE POD
WAS DESIGNED TO TRANSMIT DATA
REGARDING THE ALIEN'S
PHYSIOLOGICAL STATUS.
I BELIEVE HE WAS INSERTED
INTO THE DISTURBANCE
SO SOMEONE COULD MONITOR
HIS EXPOSURE TO THE ENVIRONMENT.
A CANARY.
ON EARTH,
MINERS USED TO TAKE CANARIES
INTO THE TUNNELS WITH THEM.
IF THE CANARY DIDN'T DIE,
THE MINERS KNEW THE AIR
WOULD BE SAFE TO BREATHE,
AND THEY COULD PROCEED.
HIS CONDITION HAS WORSENED.
HE'S LITERALLY DISINTEGRATING,
AND THERE DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
ANY WAY TO STOP IT.
I WANT TO TALK TO HIM AGAIN.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF I CAN REVIVE HIM.
FIND A WAY.
CAPTAIN, THIS MAN IS DYING
A PAINFUL DEATH.
TO KEEP HIM CONSCIOUS
IS UNETHICAL.
UNTIL I GET THE ANSWERS I NEED,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO BEND
A FEW ETHICS.
VERY WELL. I'LL DO WHAT I CAN.
NOTIFY ME WHEN HE'S CONSCIOUS.
CORPORAL.
COME IN.
THANK YOU, MA'AM.
I APPRECIATE YOUR DOING THIS.
PLEASE, SIT DOWN.
REMOVE YOUR JACKET.
I ASSUME COMMANDER TUCKER
BRIEFED YOU
ON THE PROPER
BREATHING TECHNIQUE.
HE DID.
BEGIN WITH A DEEP BREATH.
[ INHALES ]
GOOD.
[ EXHALES ]
DR. PHLOX DID CAUTION YOU
AGAINST ANY FURTHER
NEUROPRESSURE
FROM COMMANDER TUCKER?
I GOT THE LECTURE.
YOU AND COMMANDER TUCKER
APPEAR TO ENJOY
EACH OTHER'S COMPANY.
HMM. WE DO HAVE
A LOT IN COMMON.
DID HE TELL YOU WE GREW UP
LESS THAN 50 KILOMETERS
FROM EACH OTHER?
HE DIDN'T MENTION IT.
OUR HIGH SCHOOLS WERE RIVALS.
WE WENT TO
THE SAME MOVIE THEATERS.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
EXTREMELY LOW.
UNFORTUNATELY, NEITHER OF OUR
HOMETOWNS EXISTS ANYMORE.
THEY WERE BOTH DESTROYED
IN THE ATTACK.
DID YOU LOSE ANY RELATIVES?
MY FAMILY MOVED UP NORTH
A FEW YEARS AGO.
I WAS LUCKY.
COMMANDER TUCKER WAS
GREATLY AFFECTED
BY HIS SISTER'S DEATH.
HE TALKS ABOUT HER A LOT.
YOU'RE QUITE FOND OF HIM.
HMM.
WHAT'S NOT TO LIKE?
HE'S A GENTLEMAN.
HE'S GREAT TO BE AROUND.
AND HE HAS VERY NICE ARMS.
[ GASPS ]
I APOLOGIZE.
I'LL TRY NOT TO PRESS SO HARD.
WE DEVELOPED THIS SPECIALIZED
TRAINING SYSTEM
AT JUPITER STATION
A FEW MONTHS AGO.
THE GOAL IS TO HIT
AS MANY TARGETS
AS YOU CAN IN 10 SECONDS.
LIEUTENANT,
IF YOU'RE UP FOR IT?
FALL BACK.
START HIM OFF AT LEVEL TWO.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
FOUR TARGETS IN 10 SECONDS.
NOT BAD FOR A FIRST GO.
BUT YOU MIGHT SCHEDULE
A LITTLE EXTRA PRACTICE TIME.
KICK IT UP TO LEVEL FOUR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
NINE HITS.
THAT'S A MID-RANGE SCORE.
CORPORAL COLE HERE
HAS THE RECORD --
14 HITS AT LEVEL FOUR.
I WAS HAVING A LUCKY DAY.
OKAY, LET'S DO SOME SHOOTING.
WE'LL START AT LEVEL TWO
AND WORK OUR WAY UP.
WHO'D LIKE TO GO NEXT?
THAT TARGET PRACTICE
WAS SOMETHING.
SURE LOOKED A LOT EASIER
THAN IT WAS.
YOU DON'T SAY.
OH, COME ON.
YOUR SCORE GOT A LOT BETTER
AS THE SESSION WENT ON.
I STARTED PICTURING HAYES' HEAD
IN PLACE OF THE TARGET.
YOU TWO REALLY OUGHT
TO DECLARE A TRUCE.
OH, NO.
THIS IS A FIGHT TO THE DEATH.
I GUESS IF I WERE IN YOUR SHOES,
I'D BE JUST AS UPSET.
HE'S DETERMINED TO TAKE OVER
THE SECURITY OF THIS SHIP,
YOU KNOW.
YOU REALLY BELIEVE THAT?
EVERYTHING HE DOES
POINTS TO THE FACT.
IT COULD ALSO BE
THAT HE WANTS EVERYONE
TO BE AS PREPARED AS POSSIBLE.
YOU HAVE TO ADMIT, THE EXTRA
TRAINING ISN'T SUCH A BAD IDEA.
JUST DROP IT.
OKAY.
SO...WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
ABOUT YOU AND MISS COLE?
WE'RE FRIENDS.
IS EVERYONE ON THIS SHIP
WATCHING US?
YOU'RE PRETTY HARD TO MISS.
THAT'S WHAT T'POL SAID.
IS IT TRUE SHE'S GIVING
AMANDA NEUROPRESSURE NOW?
SO?
I HEARD IT WAS DAMAGE CONTROL
FROM YOUR TENDER TOUCH.
T'POL'S JUST SMOOTHING OUT SOME
OF THE ROUGH SPOTS, THAT'S ALL.
AND WHY WERE YOU
GIVING AMANDA COLE
NEUROPRESSURE, ANYWAY?
-WHAT'S IT TO YOU?
-WELL, FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
IT'S A PRETTY INTIMATE PROCEDURE
FOR JUST FRIENDS.
I DO IT WITH T'POL.
ARE YOU IMPLYING THERE'S
SOMETHING GOING ON THERE
AS WELL?
THAT'S THE RUMOR.
LOOK, FOR THE LAST TIME,
THERE'S NOTHING GOING ON
WITH ANY OF US,
BETWEEN ANY OF US.
RIGHT.
YOU'RE ALL JUST FRIENDS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HUH.
I GUESS THIS
VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE
ISN'T THAT INTIMATE AFTER ALL.
EXACTLY.
IN THAT CASE,
I'VE GOT A NASTY
LITTLE PAIN JUST --
JUST DROP IT.
[ LAUGHS ]
WE KNOW YOU WERE SENT HERE
AS SOME KIND OF
A TEST SUBJECT.
THE REGION OF SPACE
WHERE WE FOUND YOU --
WHAT IS IT?
[ GROANS ]
HIS PAIN MEDICATION
IS WEARING OFF.
-HOLD OFF A SECOND.
-CAPTAIN.
I WAS SENT AGAINST MY WILL.
I'M NOT FROM YOUR PART OF SPACE.
I COME FROM
A TRANS-DIMENSIONAL REALM.
KEEP GOING.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I WAS SENT HERE.
I FIND THAT HARD TO BELIEVE.
IT'S THE TRUTH.
I WAS A PRISONER.
BECAUSE OF MY TRANSGRESSIONS,
I'VE SPENT MY ENTIRE
ADULT LIFE INSIDE A CELL.
ONE DAY,
THE GUARDS OFFERED ME FREEDOM
IF I WOULD PARTICIPATE
IN AN EXPERIMENT.
I AGREED.
THAT'S ALL I REMEMBER
BEFORE I WOKE UP HERE.
WE FOUND YOU DRIFTING IN A POD,
HOOKED UP TO BANKS
OF MONITORING EQUIPMENT.
YOU'RE TELLING ME
YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHY?
THE EXPERIMENT WAS
IMPORTANT TO THEM.
THEY WOULDN'T ABANDON ME.
TAKE ME BACK.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IF YOU DON'T, I'LL DIE.
PLEASE!
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME?
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
WITH TRAVIS' ADJUSTMENTS
IN PLACE,
WE'VE RESUMED COURSE
FOR THE RED GIANT.
BETWEEN ALL THIS TRAINING
AND THE EXTRA SHIFTS
IN ENGINEERING,
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FORWARD
TO THIS ALL DAY.
SIT UP.
YOU AREN'T SAYING MUCH TONIGHT.
DON'T TELL ME YOU'RE STILL
UPSET ABOUT ME AND AMANDA.
I'M NOT UPSET.
IT SURE SOUNDS LIKE IT.
YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
WHY WOULD A FEW
NEUROPRESSURE SESSIONS
BETWEEN ME AND A MACO
BE SUCH A BIG DEAL?
[ SIGHS ]
UNLESS...
UNLESS WHAT?
UNLESS YOU'RE A LITTLE JEALOUS.
I DON'T EXPERIENCE JEALOUSY.
YOU'RE DOING A PRETTY FAIR
IMITATION OF IT.
I AM NOT, IN ANY WAY,
JEALOUS OF YOU
AND CORPORAL COLE.
YOU KNOW, YOUR VOICE IS TENSING
UP. IT'S A DEAD GIVEAWAY.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU WERE AN EXPERT
IN VOCAL INFLECTIONS.
I DON'T NEED TO BE
AN EXPERT TO READ YOU.
[ SIGHS ]
COME ON, ADMIT IT.
YOU'RE A LITTLE JEALOUS.
YOU'RE IMPLYING THAT
I'M ATTRACTED TO YOU.
THAT KIND OF GOES ALONG
WITH THE ASSUMPTION, DOESN'T IT?
I THINK YOU'RE MISTAKEN
ABOUT WHO'S ATTRACTED TO WHOM.
ARE YOU SAYING
I'M ATTRACTED TO YOU?
I DON'T NEED TO SAY IT.
YOU ALREADY HAVE.
I-I DON'T REMEMBER
THAT CONVERSATION.
IT WASN'T YOU.
IT WAS YOUR CLONE.
SIM TOLD ME.
SIM?
HE SAID HE HAD FEELINGS FOR ME.
HE TOLD YOU THAT?
STANDING RIGHT THERE.
WHAT THE HELL WAS HE
DOING IN YOUR ROOM?
YOUR VOICE IS TENSING UP.
NOW YOU'RE THE VOCAL EXPERT.
I DON'T NEED TO BE
AN EXPERT TO READ YOU.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
I'M -- I'M JEALOUS OF --
OF MYSELF?
YOU'RE JEALOUS?
NO, ABSOLUTELY NOT.
[ SIGHING ]
OKAY, MAYBE.
MAYBE I AM A LITTLE.
WHICH WOULD MEAN
YOU'RE ATTRACTED TO ME.
IT GOES WITH THE ASSUMPTION.
WHAT JUST HAPPENED HERE?
DID WE -- ARE WE --
YOU'RE NOT LIKE
THE OTHERS ON THIS SHIP.
THEY'RE FROM
A DIFFERENT WORLD THAN I AM.
WHAT ARE THEY CALLED,
YOUR TWO WORLDS?
MINE IS CALLED DENOBULA.
MY SHIPMATES ARE FROM EARTH.
AM I GOING TO DIE?
I'M DOING EVERYTHING I CAN.
I'M GRATEFUL TO YOU
FOR TRYING, DOCTOR.
TRY TO REST.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANS ]
OH, YOU LEAVING SO SOON?
I DON'T WANT TO DISTRACT YOU.
IT'S NO DISTRACTION.
IN FACT, I COULD USE
A SPARRING PARTNER...
IF YOU'RE UP FOR IT.
ALWAYS.
GOOD FOREARM BLOCK.
NICE BACK FIST.
SHOW ME THE COMBINATION.
UGH!
FASTER ON THAT COMBINATION.
YOU'RE IMPROVING.
YOU WANT TO KEEP THAT LEFT UP.
THAT'S IT, STAY LOOSE.
EXCELLENT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU'RE IMPROVING.
[ GRUNTS ]
SEE, YOU WERE LOOKING
AT MY HANDS
WHEN YOU SHOULD HAVE BEEN
LOOKING AT MY EYES.
OKAY, LIEUTENANT.
MAJOR.
[ GRUNTS ]
-TELL ME SOMETHING.
-WHAT?
WHY WON'T YOU
LET ME DO MY JOB?
UGH!
BECAUSE YOU'RE HERE TO ENHANCE
THE COMBAT CAPACITY
OF THIS CREW,
NOT TAKE OVER SECURITY.
IS THAT WHAT THIS IS ALL ABOUT?
YOU THINK I WANT TO REPLACE YOU?
YOU JUST CAN'T STAND TAKING
ORDERS FROM ME, CAN YOU?
UGH!
I HAVE NO PROBLEMS
TAKING ORDERS FROM YOU.
[ GROANS ]
AFTER LUNAR SURVIVAL TRAINING,
I CAN HANDLE
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
GOOD SPARRING WITH YOU.
HAYES!
UGH!
AS YOU WERE.
[ PANTING ]
WHAT WAS THAT?
IT'S A LITTLE KLINGON MOVE
I PICKED UP.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TACTICAL ALERT.
SENIOR OFFICERS
TO THEIR POSTS.
HE'S DISRUPTING SYSTEMS
AS HE GOES.
WE CAN USE THAT TO TRACK HIM.
THAT WAS
THE SECONDARY RELAY COUPLING.
HE'S ON "B" DECK.
BETWEEN THE A-1
AND A-3 BULKHEADS.
WE'RE COMING UP
ON ACCESS TUBE 17-BAKER.
HE'S MOVING IN YOUR DIRECTION.
CAN YOU BE ANY MORE SPECIFIC?
MALCOLM, STATUS!
OUR WEAPONS HAD
NO EFFECT ON HIM.
HE'S HEADING TOWARDS
THE CENTER OF THE SHIP.
ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
TUCKER.
LIEUTENANT!
UGH!
MAGNETIC CONTAINMENT
IS FLUCTUATING.
WE NEED TO REVERSE POLARITY
ON THE PLASMA COILS.
IT'LL TRIGGER A FEEDBACK PULSE.
TURN THE T-VALVE
ALL THE WAY TO THE LEFT.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S SEE
IF YOU CAN HANDLE THIS.
AAH!
MORNING.
COMMANDER.
COFFEE, STRONG.
SOME NIGHT.
EVENTFUL.
I DON'T KNOW WHO DID
MORE DAMAGE TO THE ENGINE,
THE ALIEN OR MALCOLM.
HOW LONG BEFORE
WE CAN GET UNDERWAY?
[ SIGHS ]
ANOTHER DAY, AT LEAST.
I, UH -- I GUESS
WE SHOULD TALK
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED LAST NIGHT.
I'VE BEEN BRIEFED
ON THE SITUATION.
WELL, I WAS REFERRING TO
WHAT HAPPENED BETWEEN US
IN YOUR QUARTERS.
I GUESS I'LL GO FIRST.
I...
ACTUALLY,
WHY DON'T YOU GO FIRST?
I SUPPOSE I SHOULD THANK YOU...
NO NEED TO THANK ME.
...FOR FACILITATING
MY EXPLORATION
OF HUMAN SEXUALITY.
I'M NOT SURE I FOLLOW.
IT'S ONE OF THE MANY ASPECTS
OF YOUR SPECIES
WHICH I'VE BEEN
MEANING TO EXPLORE
SINCE I LEFT THE HIGH COMMAND.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SOUNDS LIKE
YOU'RE SAYING THAT LAST NIGHT
WAS SOME KIND OF EXPERIMENT.
I WOULDN'T USE THAT TERM.
BUT THAT'S THE GENERAL IDEA.
ARE YOU GETTING EMOTIONAL?
NO, I'M NOT GETTING EMOTIONAL.
I JUST DON'T LIKE
BEING COMPARED TO A LAB RAT.
I'M SORRY IF I OFFENDED YOU.
[ SCOFFS ]
FORGET IT.
I'D, UH, APPRECIATE IT IF WE
COULD KEEP THIS BETWEEN US.
IN FACT, WE SHOULD PROBABLY
JUST FORGET IT EVER HAPPENED.
AGREED.
DOESN'T MEAN WE CAN'T KEEP DOING
THE NEUROPRESSURE, THOUGH.
DR. PHLOX SAYS YOU HAVE
A DETACHED RETINA.
A BRUISED LEFT KIDNEY.
WE'RE IN A DANGEROUS REGION
OF SPACE.
WE'RE TRYING TO STOP AN ALIEN
RACE FROM DESTROYING EARTH.
WE FACE ATTACKS
FROM ALL SIDES,
ENEMIES EVERYWHERE WE GO.
THE LAST THING I NEED IS TO HEAR
THAT TWO OF MY SENIOR OFFICERS
HAVE BEEN ADMITTED TO SICK BAY
BECAUSE THEY SUDDENLY REGRESSED
TO THE LEVEL OF 5-YEAR-OLDS!
-CAPTAIN --
-DON'T TRY TO TELL ME
WHO STARTED IT!
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE PROBLEM IS
BETWEEN YOU TWO,
AND TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I DON'T CARE.
BUT I WANT IT SETTLED RIGHT NOW!
SETTLE IT! THAT'S AN ORDER!
THERE'S NO PROBLEM, CAPTAIN.
IT'S SETTLED, SIR.
HOW ARE THE DRILLS GOING?
-GOOD, SIR.
-VERY GOOD, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
PLEASE COME TO SICK BAY,
CAPTAIN.
THE ALIEN HAS
REGAINED CONSCIOUSNESS.
ON MY WAY.
THINK WE'RE DISMISSED?
I'M AFRAID THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO.
YOU WEREN'T SENT HERE
AGAINST YOUR WILL.
YOU KNEW EXACTLY
WHAT YOUR MISSION WAS.
WHAT WERE YOUR PEOPLE
TRYING TO DO?
YOU TRIED TO DESTROY MY SHIP!
WHY?
ANSWER ME!
WHEN THE XINDI DESTROY EARTH,
MY PEOPLE WILL PREVAIL.
UGH!