Porthos! No, come back here!
Porthos! Stop! Return!
Well, uh, heel! That's it. Heel!
Oh, Porthos.
( sighs )
( whimpering )
( barking )
All right, but just for a moment.
( whimpering )
That's enough.
You can come and see him again tomorrow.
Oh, yes.
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And i will see my dream
come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna
change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart
will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength
of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend
or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got, I've got ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
Ah, it says here that, uh,
canines can be quite territorial.
Is that why you keep returning
to the Captain's quarters?
( chuckles )
Hmm...
On Earth, a dog called Scruffers
traveled 3,000 kilometers
attempting to reunite
with its human keeper.
( exclaims ) I heard of a Pycan space moth
that drifted half a light-year
trying to return to its homeworld.
But I don't believe it had a name.
( sighs )
I could use a walk. How about you?
( computer beeps )
Dear Dr. Lucas, I apologize for the delay
in responding to your last letter.
As you can imagine,
the crew and I have been quite busy.
In we go.
I was deeply saddened to hear
about your colleagues
lost in the Xindi attack.
You have my condolences.
It's unfortunate you were forced
to cut your time on Denobula short,
but, uh, obviously you're needed on Earth.
Perhaps when our mission
is successfully completed,
I'll see you back in San Francisco.
The Expanse... an extremely curious place.
For example, we've recently encountered
a phenomenon that--
( barking )
Do you want one of these?
( chuckles ) I doubt you'd like it.
It's a leech, you know.
It will clean out your intestinal tract.
Don't tell the Captain.
( chuckles )
I currently find myself
in somewhat unsettling circumstances,
Dr. Lucas,
although they have allowed me the luxury
of catching up on my correspondence.
We first encountered the phenomenon
responsible for this situation
two days ago.
T'POL: It's directly on our route
to Azati Prime.
Why didn't sensors pick it up before now?
Because it wasn't there before now.
It's similar to the phenomenon
we encountered several weeks ago.
A trans-dimensional disturbance?
This region is being rapidly
reconfigured as we speak.
How long would it take to go around it?
Two weeks.
-Another detour.
-T'POL: Perhaps not.
Since this region was formed
only recently,
it hasn't been completely reconfigured.
We should still be able
to cross it safely.
You said nothing from our universe
could survive inside these things.
-Doctor.
-PHLOX: That's true,
unless we take
the appropriate precautions.
The reconfigured space
disrupts the human neocortex.
But I can counteract the effects
by dampening the crew's
neurological activity.
It would be like, uh, oh,
shutting down the main computer
to protect it from an ion storm.
How do you plan to shut down
our neocortexes?
Quite simply, I can place each of you
in a comatose state
until we've passed through
the affected region.
How quickly can we get across it?
Less than an hour at warp 4.
I don't want to risk
going to warp in there.
Who knows what kind of effect
this disturbance will have
on our warp field?
We'll be safer sticking to impulse.
You'll have to keep us in comas for...
( sighs ) At least four days.
That's still less time than
it would take to go around it.
Can you keep us under that long?
Shouldn't cause any problems.
PHLOX: Commander Tucker
was not too keen on my plan.
However, I was able
to convince Captain Archer.
( grunts )
Since my Denobulan physiology is immune
to the effects of the disturbance,
I volunteered to watch over the crew.
So far... Ah...
They've been no trouble at all.
While the computer is controlling
most of the ship's systems,
I was given a quick tutorial,
just in case.
Despite the dire circumstances,
I must say I relished the challenge...
And soon developed a newfound respect
for Ensign Mayweather.
( inaudible )
TUCKER: You need to check this
every two hours, minimum.
Every two hours.
If the impulse manifolds get clogged,
the engines will overload.
That would be very bad.
I imagine it would.
No offense, Doc,
but under normal circumstances,
I wouldn't even let you in here
without four years
of Starfleet training under your belt.
These are hardly normal circumstances.
Listen.
If something happens,
something you can't handle,
-I want you to wake me up.
-I can't do that.
Even a few minutes of exposure
would cause permanent damage.
If it comes down to saving me or the ship?
Look. I'm making it easy for you, OK?
ARCHER: How's the rest of the crew doing?
Sleeping peacefully, except for you.
Now, lie back.
-Doctor--
-Ah!
Please, Captain, I've told you
the procedure is completely safe.
I'm sure it is, but I--
Captain,
I have already had this discussion
with Commander Tucker, Lieutenant Reed,
and virtually
every other officer on the ship.
"I'm not comfortable being incapacitated."
"I really should be at my post."
"I'm willing to risk staying awake."
Well, you can't, nor do you need to.
I assure you,
I have everything well in hand.
I know, Doctor. As captain of this ship,
I'm the one who's responsible
for everyone aboard.
There's aren't many people
I'd willingly turn
that responsibility over to.
You're one of them.
Ah. ( chuckles )
Well, uh, thank you, Captain.
I just wanted to say that
before you put me under.
PHLOX: I must say, Dr. Lucas,
that I appreciated the Captain's
vote of confidence.
I had, in fact,
been feeling some trepidation
over the responsibility I'd been handed.
But after two days at the helm,
the ship is running perfectly.
( clatter )
Hello?
Nonetheless, I'm not ashamed to admit
I'll be relieved when
I can wake up the crew in, uh...
Two days, 16 hours, and 43 minutes.
( singing in Denobulan )
( animals chattering )
I know, I know. I'm sorry I'm late.
I don't want the vessel with a pestle.
I want the chalice from the what?
-The chalice from the palace.
-Hmm?
It's a little crystal chalice
with a figure of a palace.
Does the chalice from the palace
have the pellet with the poison?
No, the pellet with the poison
is in the vessel with a pestle.
-MAN: Oh, the pestle with the vessel.
-WOMAN: The vessel with a pestle.
MAN: What about the palace
from the chalice?
WOMAN 2: Not the palace from the chalice.
The chalice from the palace.
-MAN: Where's the pellet with the poison?
-WOMAN 2: In the vessel with a pestle.
-WOMAN: Don't you see?
-( Porthos whimpers )
The pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with a pestle.
The chalice from the palace
has the brew that is true.
-So easy, I can say it.
-Well, then, you find it.
Listen carefully.
-( clang )
-The pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with a pestle.
The chalice from the palace
has the brew that is true.
MAN: Where the pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with a pestle...
Did you hear that?
-WOMAN: Good man!
-WOMAN 2: Just remember that.
MAN: Sir Giacomo
Sir Giacomo, into your armor.
And you to your place in the pavilion.
-( clang )
-The pellet with the poison...
-The pellet with the poison--
-Computer, mute sound.
( inaudible )
( clang )
That doesn't sound normal, does it?
I suppose we should investigate, hmm?
I'm not going alone.
Come, Porthos. Come!
( sighs )
Oh, I'd be better off
talking to my Pyrithian bat.
Perhaps we were letting our imaginations
run away with us, hmm?
I should never have let Mr. Tucker talk me
into watching The Exorcist last week.
( clang )
Hello?
It's Dr. Phlox.
-( Porthos barking )
-Porthos!
Porthos, come back here!
Porthos!
( gas hissing )
( scoffs )
Well, now don't you feel foolish?
( clatter )
( sighs )
I called out. Didn't you hear me?
I was running a diagnostic.
Do you require my assistance?
( sighs )
What are you doing here?
I thought it was movie night.
I could hear that all the way
from the mess hall.
I'll make a note of it
in the maintenance log.
Hmm.
Bangs, squeaks, rattling chains.
Is this a starship or a haunted house?
Are you all right, Doctor?
You seem somewhat agitated.
Well, considering you nearly
sent me into cardiac shock...
I apologize if I startled you.
You're certain that's all?
Oh, I have had a slight headache
since we entered this region.
Perhaps Vulcans and Earth canines
are better able to adapt to it
than Denobulans.
How are you, hmm?
I've barely seen you the last two days.
I've had my duties to attend to.
The rest of the time I've spent
in my quarters reading, meditating.
Then you're due for a night out.
Why don't you join Porthos and me?
I'd like to complete the diagnostic.
The movie's quite amusing.
No, thank you.
T'Pol.
I, um, uh...
Perhaps you'll share a meal with me later.
If you like.
Ah...
( humming )
( computer beeping )
( clattering )
Hello?
-( humming )
-( clatter )
T'Pol?
Is that you?
( clatter )
Stop!
-Phlox to T'Pol.
-Go ahead.
Would you mind
not creeping around the ship
like a Draxxan cloud viper?
T'POL: Doctor?
Please. I wouldn't have imagined
that Vulcans engaged in childish games.
T'POL: I don't understand.
What were you doing
in engineering just now?
T'POL: Doctor, I'm on the bridge.
Ah!
I hope you don't, uh,
mind eating here in the galley.
The mess hall seems a bit, oh, melancholy.
All the empty chairs.
T'POL: This is fine.
Fine.
My fifth grandmother made this
for each of my weddings.
Chef's tried to prepare it,
but he never gets it quite right.
( exclaiming )
Yes, his Plomeek broth
leaves something to be desired as well.
I always thought so,
but, uh, I was afraid to mention it.
( sighs )
Mmm. ( chuckles )
T'Pol, um, you're sure you
weren't in engineering today?
Quite sure.
What were you doing there?
I'm responsible for
monitoring the engines.
We're supposed to be assisting each other.
It's a large ship
for two people to maintain.
Do you have anything to report?
Doctor?
I could have sworn there was
someone in that room with me.
-A member of the crew?
-No.
Everyone except us
is in deep neuro-sedation.
Then obviously you were mistaken.
Obviously. ( chuckles )
You've never been to Denobula, have you?
No.
The cities are quite crowded...
by choice, not by necessity.
The atmosphere is vibrant, communal.
It sounds fascinating.
What I'm saying is that
we're a sociable people.
Being alone on Enterprise,
just the two of us,
has proven more stressful than I imagined.
Two people aren't even enough
for a Denobulan marriage--
A proper one, anyway.
I'm sorry I haven't been better company.
That isn't what I meant.
I know.
It is ironic, however,
that I should be your sole companion.
Unlike your people, most Vulcans
will go to great lengths to find solitude.
At times, it has been trying for me
to coexist with 80 humans,
especially the more irrational ones.
Mm, such as, uh, Commander Tucker.
I've found the last two days
to be a welcome respite.
I understand, but I, for one,
will never complain again
when I can't get a good seat
on movie night.
Despite the tragic circumstances
surrounding your homecoming, Dr. Lucas,
you must be happy to return to Earth.
( chuckles )
As I've mentioned before,
I have no regrets
about accepting my position on Enterprise.
However, it has struck me recently
how much I miss
the familiar pleasures of my home.
( chuckles )
You've experienced the nightclubs
in our Kaybin district,
so you know the excitement of meeting
a new companion or two,
the intimacy that can develop so quickly
when all parties are receptive.
You humans are a truly
remarkable species, Dr. Lucas,
but when Enterprise
has accomplished its mission,
I look forward to being
among Denobulans again...
The more of them, the better.
Good afternoon, Captain.
How are we feeling today?
Ah. Neurochemistry looks excellent.
Theta waves are good.
You should wake up extremely well rested.
( creaking )
( creaking continues )
( gasping )
Phlox to T'Pol.
Internal sensors don't show
any additional bio-signs.
I told you, it was outside of the ship,
on the hull.
There are no life-forms
anywhere in this vicinity.
What about alien vessels?
You can see for yourself
there's nothing there.
You said this reconfigured space
could be affecting our systems.
What if it's interfering with our sensors?
That's possible,
but we should consider
another explanation.
You mentioned you were having difficulty
adjusting to the solitude
of the past few days.
I didn't imagine it! I saw something.
Outside the ship, crawling on the hull.
What about what I saw in engineering?
You ran the scans yourself.
There is nothing unusual onboard.
You said you haven't slept much
since we entered this disturbance.
Perhaps you should return
to your quarters, try to rest.
I need to finish my rounds.
( humming )
Get away from her!
( screeching )
( gasps )
( clattering )
( screeching )
-Phlox to T'Pol.
-Go ahead, Doctor.
It's the Xindi. They're onboard.
We'll need to arm ourselves. I saw two.
There could be more of them.
There's nothing on the sensors.
Then the sensors must be wrong!
Doctor.
Phlox!
I thought you were going to get some rest.
They were real! I saw them!
If that's true,
then how did they get on the ship?
Ah!
All external hatches
and docking ports are sealed.
They could have transporter technology.
There were no transporter signatures.
What difference does it make
how they got onboard?
If we wake up
Lieutenant Reed or the Macos,
they will be incapacitated within minutes,
dead within hours.
It is up to us
to deal with this situation.
I plan to start on "G" deck
and work my way up.
I'm going to stop them
whether you help me or not.
( sighs )
We've searched four decks.
That leaves three to go.
If there are Xindi aboard,
why are they concealing themselves?
They could be trying
to destroy Enterprise.
What better time than while
the crew is incapacitated?
( beeping )
A bio-sign.
There are over 80 bio-signs aboard,
not counting your pets in sick bay.
This isn't human.
Neither are your pets.
Ah. I can't lock onto it.
There must be some interference,
possibly from the reconfigured space.
You said it wasn't affecting our sensors.
I said it wasn't affecting main sensors.
That hand scanner is far less powerful.
You know that.
I have it.
It's just ahead.
( clicking )
Doctor!
( whimpers )
It's all right.
Fortunately, I'm not very proficient
with hand weapons.
How did he get out?
I... I believe I, um...
We went for a walk earlier.
I might have neglected to put him back
in my quarters.
And you simply forgot?
I've been distracted!
I would've thought this
could tell the difference
between a giant insect and a beagle!
-It can, if you use it properly.
-You're the science officer!
You might have offered
some assistance in that area.
You feel I haven't been helpful?
How would you characterize
the two hours I wasted
searching for a figment
of your imagination?
-I'm not delusional!
-Are you certain?
As I recall, you once told Ensign Sato
that it's considered healthy
for Denobulans to hallucinate.
It's how you release stress.
You've been under a lot of stress lately,
haven't you, Doctor?
It's not unheard of, but I--
You said you've been having headaches.
Is there anything else
you care to tell me?
I'm fine!
You nearly shot the Captain's dog!
I'm going to recalibrate this
to exclude canine bio-signs,
and then I'm going to finish
searching this ship.
I am not seeing things,
and I intend to prove it!
( computer beeps )
Ensign Sato to the doctor!
Hoshi?
( water running )
Ensign?
Hoshi?
What are you doing?
I have to put you back
under sedation immediately!
You'll suffer permanent damage.
Hoshi.
You did this.
What?
You said we'd be safe.
Let me get you to sick bay.
You promised us!
T'Pol...
Please meet me in sick bay immediately.
Where have you been? I was calling you.
( gasps )
Captain... W-what are you doing up?
T'Pol woke me.
She said something was wrong.
I don't know what's happening.
She said you've been seeing things,
something about Xindi onboard the ship.
You're not concerned about that?
I'm more concerned about you.
I obviously expected too much from you.
You're not real.
Why don't you go to your quarters?
Lie down. I'll take over.
You did the best you could.
-You are not real!
-Doctor?
( gasping )
I was so busy monitoring the crew,
I never thought to run
another neural scan on myself.
The effects are subtle
and difficult to detect,
but there are disruptions
deep within my neocortex.
You were right.
I was hallucinating.
Are you in danger?
I don't believe there'll be
any permanent damage.
However, it's obviously
affecting my judgment.
I have no choice but to put myself
under neuro-sedation
and ask you to look after the crew.
I don't have the medical expertise.
With your scientific background,
you should have no problems.
I have my own duties.
I can't possibly monitor the entire crew.
It won't be for long.
We'll be coming out
of the disturbance in less than six hours.
T'Pol, I'm asking for your help.
I can't.
Why not?
When we were searching the ship,
I... became irritated with you.
Apparently I deserved it.
You don't understand.
I was on the verge
of losing control of my emotions.
This reconfigured space
is affecting me as well.
Why didn't you tell me?
I'd hoped to control it,
but it's proven more difficult
than I thought.
The crew is better off in your hands.
I doubt that.
I nearly killed Porthos, remember?
What if one of these delusions causes me
to open an airlock
or shut down life support?
-You won't do that.
-How do you know?
Because your duty is to look out
for the welfare of this crew.
Why do you think the Captain
allowed you to sedate him
over Commander Tucker's objections?
Because he trusts you, as do I.
I'm not sure I trust myself.
Just a few more hours, Doctor.
PHLOX: So, Dr. Lucas,
while the past few days
have proven challenging,
both T'Pol and I are relieved
that our adventure is nearly over.
Once we've confirmed
we're out of the disturbance,
I can begin waking the senior officers.
My medical staff should be next.
They can assist me
with the rest of the, uh...
Well, we should have been
out of the disturbance half an hour ago.
There could have been some slight
navigational discrepancies.
I thought space travel
was supposed to be precise.
Not always. Check long-range sensors.
What do you think I'm doing?
There's more than a slight discrepancy.
This can't be correct.
We're nearly a quarter of
a light-year from the far edge.
At our current rate of speed,
we won't be out of this for another...
10 weeks!
Auto-navigation is still engaged.
Engines are online. Why aren't we through?
The reconfigured space has expanded.
But we knew it would!
Travis said our course
and speed would compensate.
T'Pol?
Obviously the rate
of expansion has accelerated.
We need to increase speed.
We're already at full impulse.
As you can see, that's insufficient.
We need to go to warp.
Commander Tucker said
it would be too dangerous.
We don't know what might happen.
What do you propose?
Keeping the crew comatose
for the next 10 weeks?
PHLOX: All right. What do we do first?
( voice breaking ) I'm afraid
I may not be of much assistance.
Do I need to keep reminding you
you are the science officer?
I already told you
I'm finding it difficult to focus.
On your worst day, you're more qualified
to operate the warp engines than I am.
Unfortunately, this is by far
one of my worst days.
I'm a physician, not an engineer!
You hold a dozen scientific degrees.
None of them are in warp theory!
( sighs )
The procedures for restarting
the reactor are in the database.
Are you suggesting I read the manual?
"Output must be confined
to within 300 and 312 millicochranes
to prevent fusion
of the dilithium matrix."
That seems simple enough.
"Unless the spatial-compression index
is greater than 5.62%
or the ship is within two parsecs
of a class-C
gravimetric field distortion"?
I realize this is a complex procedure.
Complex? This is utterly baffling.
It might as well be written
in ancient Klingon,
for all the sense I can make of it.
( sighs )
I'm sorry.
I understand.
I just wish I could be more helpful.
You're doing fine.
We have to close the plasma relays
before we can begin the startup sequence.
Would you mind?
What the hell are you doing?
I told you not to mess
with the warp engines.
I don't have time for this.
You better make time, Doc.
I told you, you can't start
the warp reactor inside this disturbance.
Actually, you told me
it would be difficult, not impossible.
That machine was designed
to manipulate space,
to violate the laws of motion.
You make the tiniest mistake,
you'll collapse the warp field,
you'll crush this ship.
Thank you for the warning.
You're gonna screw this up, Phlox.
-Go away!
-You're gonna kill everybody!
Can't you see I'm busy?
Doctor! Are you all right?
Fine.
Doctor?
I can't find the plasma relays.
I'll do it myself.
Deuterium pressure is nominal.
Antimatter constrictor coils are online.
Warp 2, hmm, should be sufficient?
Shall we try?
The intermix is stable.
A warp field is forming. ( laughing )
-( computer beeping )
-What's wrong?
I-I-I don't know.
I followed the procedures exactly.
-What did I do wrong?
-You need to--
What?
What, T'Pol? Help me!
( stammering )
Is it... The particle confinement?
Perhaps you should increase it.
Well, how do I do that?
Oh!
Particle confinement.
Particle confinement!
Doctor... Perhaps we should
wake Commander Tucker.
He'll die.
If we destroy the ship, we'll all die.
I know.
If we can't accomplish our mission,
billions of people on Earth could die.
Isn't it logical to sacrifice one life
to save so many?
I'm not willing
to make that sacrifice yet!
Particle confinement!
Increase power to magnetic
constriction coils!
T'Pol!
Oh, here!
( rumbling stops )
The field is stabilizing.
It's holding.
Then I suggest we go to warp.
Engaging warp engines.
Warp 1.1.
1.2.
( whooshing )
Pressure on the hull's increasing.
What are you doing?
Lieutenant Reed insisted
on showing me how to transfer
power to the hull plating...
Just in case.
It seems to be working.
Warp 1.8.
1.9.
Warp 2! ( laughing )
Doctor.
Ah, ah, ah! Lie still.
Your neocortex may need
a few moments to warm up.
Are we th-through the disturbance?
Yes. I'll begin waking
the rest of the crew shortly.
Any...problems?
Oh, a few minor glitches.
It will all be in my log.
( sighs )
If you're feeling up to it,
you have a visitor.
Oh, hey.
Thanks, Doctor.
How are you feeling?
-A little woozy.
-I'm not surprised.
You haven't eaten anything in four days.
Get to the mess hall.
Aye, aye, Doc.
-I'll assist you in waking the others.
-Oh, that won't be necessary.
I appreciate the offer,
but, uh, you need some rest.
Let me walk you to your quarters.
-Doctor's orders?
-Mm-hmm.
-Thank you.
I'll stop by and check on you
in a few hours.
PHLOX: As you might guess, Dr. Lucas,
I had considered deleting this letter
and starting over,
since large sections of it
are now obviously fictitious.
However, I decided that
my delusional account
would probably prove entertaining.
As always, you have my best wishes.
Your friend and colleague, Phlox.
May I join you?
Of course.
( sighs )
Commander Tucker was complaining
that it will take him days
to realign the warp coils.
( laughs )
Yes, he gave me quite a talking to.
He also said, and I quote,
"Phlox did one hell of a job."
MAN: Oh. Excuse me, Doctor.
You must have enjoyed
having the ship to yourself.
It wasn't nearly as empty
as I anticipated.