PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
THE INSECTOID SHIP'S
BEEN DAMAGED.
TARGET THE SECOND ONE.
IS THAT WHAT THIS IS ALL ABOUT?
YOU THINK I WANT TO REPLACE YOU?
OH, YOU JUST CAN'T STAND TAKING
ORDERS FROM ME, CAN YOU?
TELL ME SOMETHING.
WHAT?
WHY WON'T YOU LET ME DO MY JOB?
I WANT TO KNOW WHERE
YOU'RE BUILDING THE WEAPON.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THE HELL YOU DON'T.
THERE'S A REFERENCE TO A PLANET
HE VISITED RECENTLY.
AZATI PRIME.
THE COORDINATES
MATCH THE LOCATION
OF ONE OF THE RED GIANTS.
SET A COURSE FOR AZATI PRIME,
MAXIMUM WARP.
MAGNIFY.
IT'S DEFINITELY XINDI, SIR.
THE HULL COMPOSITION MATCHES
THE OTHER SHIPS WE'VE SEEN.
IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE A REPTILIAN
OR A PRIMATE DESIGN.
BIO-SIGNS?
NONE THAT I CAN DETECT.
THERE'S NO ATMOSPHERE ABOARD.
ANYONE ELSE IN THE SYSTEM?
NO, SIR.
PUT A TEAM TOGETHER.
AYE, SIR.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
WE'LL TAKE THEM
BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
TELL PHLOX I WANT
A COMPLETE AUTOPSY.
THE MAJOR AND I WILL
SEARCH THE PORT SIDE.
SEE IF YOU CAN ACCESS
THEIR SHIP'S DATABASE.
[ SCANNER BEEPING ]
IT'S A COMPUTER INTERFACE.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN DOWNLOAD.
MY FATHER WOULD LOVE TO
GET A LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
HE'S FASCINATED BY INSECTS,
ALWAYS FILLING THE HOUSE UP
WITH BUGS HE'S COLLECTED.
DRIVES MY MOTHER CRAZY.
MAYBE WE CAN BRING HOME
SOMETHING NEW
FOR HIS COLLECTION.
[ LAUGHS ]
IT'S HEAVILY REINFORCED.
[ HATCH CLOSES ]
[ AIR HISSES ]
IT'S PRESSURIZING.
OXYGEN-NITROGEN ATMOSPHERE.
AFTER YOU.
[ SIGHS ]
A LITTLE STALE,
BUT BREATHABLE.
BIO-SIGNS.
VERY FAINT.
COMING FROM IN HERE.
SOME KIND OF SHUTTLECRAFT?
MORE LIKE AN ASSAULT VEHICLE.
I'M READING
A HALF-DOZEN PARTICLE CANNONS,
TORPEDO LAUNCHERS.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
You'd better get over here, sir.
THE DNA IS IDENTICAL
TO THE BODIES WE FOUND.
THEY WOULD APPEAR TO BE
THE CREW'S OFFSPRING.
A HATCHERY?
THEY BUILT THIS PLACE
TO TAKE QUITE A BEATING.
REINFORCED BULKHEADS,
BACKUP POWER SYSTEMS.
31 EGGS ARE STILL VIABLE.
THEY WON'T SURVIVE FOR LONG.
BIO-SUPPORT'S LOSING POWER.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN REPAIR IT?
I WOULDN'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE TO START.
THERE'S A SHUTTLECRAFT
IN THEIR PORT BAY.
GET IT BACK TO THE SHIP.
I WANT AN ANALYSIS
OF THEIR TACTICAL SYSTEMS
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
AYE, SIR.
DID YOU FIND THEIR BRIDGE?
I'M NOT CERTAIN THERE IS ONE.
THEIR COMMAND FUNCTIONS
APPEAR TO BE DISTRIBUTED
THROUGH VARIOUS --
-UGH!
-CAPTAIN!
[ GASPS ]
I'M ALL RIGHT.
WE SHOULD GET YOU TO SICKBAY.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
MM, A MILD NEUROTOXIN,
LIKELY PART OF AN AUTONOMIC
DEFENSE SYSTEM.
THE EGG PROBABLY
CONSIDERED YOU A THREAT.
HUMANS SEEM TO HAVE THAT EFFECT
ON THE XINDI.
[ CHUCKLES ]
AH, AN ANALGESIC SHOULD
TAKE CARE OF THE IRRITATION.
MALCOLM'S BRINGING YOU
TWO DEAD INSECTOIDS.
HMM?
I WANT YOU TO LEARN AS MUCH
AS YOU CAN ABOUT THEM.
UNDERSTOOD.
WE'VE LOCATED THEIR ARMORY,
FOUND SEVERAL PARTICLE WEAPONS
AND TORPEDO CASINGS.
WHAT ABOUT THE DATA
YOU RECOVERED?
ENSIGN SATO'S TRANSLATING IT.
WE'LL BE READY TO LEAVE ORBIT
AS SOON
AS THE XINDI SHUTTLE'S ABOARD.
[ RUMBLING ]
WE'VE CLEARED THE THERMOSPHERE.
[ THUD ]
YOU MIGHT WANT TO DO A BETTER
JOB SECURING OUR GUESTS.
I THINK IT'S SAFE
TO ASSUME IT'S DEAD.
JUST BEING CAUTIOUS.
[ GRUNTS ]
CERTAIN INSECTS ON EARTH
ARE KNOWN TO HIBERNATE.
DO YOU INTEND TO SHOOT ME,
MAJOR?
IT'S NOT YOU I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
I'VE BEEN GOING OVER
THE RESULTS
FROM THE LAST TRAINING SESSION.
YOUR SENIOR OFFICERS HAVE SHOWN
A LOT OF IMPROVEMENT,
BUT I THINK THEY CAN DO BETTER.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
I'D LIKE TO SCHEDULE
SOME MORE TARGET PRACTICE
FOR MONDAY EVENING.
THAT WON'T GO OVER WELL
WITH COMMANDER TUCKER.
MONDAY NIGHT IS MOVIE NIGHT.
MAYBE HE CAN SACRIFICE
SOME LEISURE TIME
FOR THE SAKE OF THIS MISSION.
THE SENIOR OFFICERS
DO HAVE OTHER DUTIES.
WE CAN'T ALL SPEND OUR TIME
PLAYING HOLOGRAPHIC GAMES
IN THE ARMORY.
I'M NOT SURE THAT'S HOW
THE CAPTAIN WOULD SEE IT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Enterprise to Shuttlepod 2.
You're clear to approach.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
DEPLOY THE DOCKING ARM.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I THINK WE FIGURED OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM.
ONE OF THEIR NACELLES FRACTURED
WHILE THEY WERE COMING OUT
OF A SUBSPACE VORTEX.
THEY PROBABLY TRIED TO MAKE
AN EMERGENCY LANDING
ON THIS PLANET.
ACCORDING TO PHLOX,
THE INSECTOIDS WE FOUND
WEREN'T KILLED IN THE CRASH --
THEY SUFFOCATED?
MOST OF THE CREW APPEAR TO HAVE
DIED WHEN THEY TRANSFERRED
THEIR LIFE SUPPORT
TO THE HATCHERY.
THEY SACRIFICED THEMSELVES
TO SAVE THEIR CHILDREN.
YOU SAID THE HATCHERY
IS LOSING BIO-SUPPORT.
HOW LONG WILL IT LAST?
ANOTHER DAY, AT MOST.
I WANT YOU TO ASSIGN A TEAM
TO REPAIR IT.
-CAPTAIN?
-WHAT ABOUT AZATI PRIME?
IT'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
THIS IS A SENTIENT SPECIES.
WE CAN'T ABANDON THEM.
CAPTAIN, WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
WHY THE HELL NOT?
I'VE GOT HALF A MIND TO TAKE
A PLASMA TORCH TO THAT PLACE.
WHAT IF WE FOUND A NURSERY
FILLED WITH 31 INFANT PRIMATES?
WOULD YOU WANT TO TORCH THEM?
THE XINDI ARE TRYING
TO DESTROY EARTH
BECAUSE THEY HEARD
THAT HUMANS ARE RUTHLESS.
THIS IS A CHANCE
TO PROVE THEM WRONG.
WE CAN BRING THE EGGS ABOARD,
RECONFIGURE ONE
OF THE CARGO BAYS.
I ALREADY TALKED TO PHLOX.
HE SAYS THEY'RE INTEGRATED
INTO THE HATCHERY WALLS.
IF WE REMOVE THEM, THEY'LL DIE.
SIR, THIS IS CRAZY. THESE PEOPLE
ARE TRYING TO KILL US.
THIS ISN'T OPEN FOR DISCUSSION.
I'LL LEAD THE ENGINEERING TEAM.
I NEED YOU UP HERE
TO HELP TRAVIS FIGURE OUT
HOW TO OPERATE
THAT XINDI SHUTTLE.
CAPTAIN.
I'VE MADE MY DECISION.
GET TO WORK.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
JANUARY 8, 2154.
WE'VE BEEN IN ORBIT
FOR MORE THAN A DAY.
THE CREW IS RESTLESS,
EAGER TO RESUME OUR MISSION.
BUT I'M CERTAIN MY DECISION
TO STAY WAS THE RIGHT ONE.
THEY MAY KNOW HOW
TO BUILD A WEAPONS SYSTEM,
BUT THESE PEOPLE
COULD LEARN A THING OR TWO
ABOUT DESIGNING
A COMFORTABLE CHAIR.
FOR AN INSECTOID,
MAYBE THEY ARE COMFORTABLE.
AND THE POWER GRID
DOESN'T MAKE MUCH SENSE.
ALMOST HALF OF IT IS ROUTED
TO STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY.
YOU COULD PROBABLY FLY
THIS THING INSIDE A GAS GIANT.
ASSUMING YOU COULD
FIGURE OUT HOW TO FLY IT.
THIS ICON LOOKS LIKE IT MIGHT
REPRESENT THE IMPULSE MANIFOLDS.
GIVE IT A SHOT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
I DON'T THINK THIS SHIP
LIKES US VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO REMOVE
THE RELAYS HERE AND HERE.
THAT SHOULD DISABLE
THE SECURITY PROTOCOLS.
WE CAN'T INITIALIZE THE ENGINES
WITHOUT THEM.
WHAT ABOUT THE SHIP
ON THE SURFACE?
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SALVAGE WHAT WE NEED.
YEAH.
ANY WORD ON HOW MUCH LONGER HE'S
PLANNING TO STAY IN ORBIT?
THE REPAIRS ARE MOVING SLOW.
I'D BE THE LAST TO QUESTION
THE CAPTAIN'S ORDERS,
BUT DOESN'T IT SEEM A LITTLE ODD
THAT WE'RE STAYING HERE
TO SAVE A NEST OF XINDI?
THE CAPTAIN THINKS
IT'S THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
WE MAY BE AT WAR, BUT THESE
CREATURES NEED OUR HELP.
MEANWHILE, THEIR BIG BROTHERS
ARE TRYING TO DESTROY EARTH.
EVERY DAY WE STAY HERE
GIVES THEM MORE TIME
TO FINISH THEIR WEAPON.
LOOK.
THERE'S A CHANCE
WE'LL RUN INTO MORE INSECTOIDS
WHEN WE REACH THAT RED GIANT.
SPENDING AN EXTRA DAY OR TWO
STUDYING THEIR TACTICAL SYSTEMS
MIGHT BE USEFUL.
AH, CAPTAIN.
I'VE, UH, LEARNED QUITE A BIT
ABOUT THIS FASCINATING FELLOW.
UH, PERHAPS "FELLOW"
IS THE WRONG WORD.
THEIR SPECIES IS GENDERLESS.
THEN WHO MADE
ALL THOSE EGGS?
THEY REPRODUCE ASEXUALLY.
EACH ADULT APPEARS CAPABLE
OF PRODUCING MULTIPLE EGG SACS.
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED
IF EVERY INSECTOID VESSEL
HAD ITS OWN HATCHERY.
I'D ESTIMATE THEIR LIFESPAN
IS NO MORE
THAN, OH, 12 EARTH YEARS.
THIS INDIVIDUAL MAY BE ONE OF
THE ELDER MEMBERS OF THE CREW.
IT WAS NEARLY 10 YEARS OLD.
WHAT ABOUT THE HATCHERY?
WHEN WILL THE EGGS MATURE?
WITHOUT KNOWING MORE ABOUT THEIR
INCUBATION CYCLE,
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO SAY,
BUT, UH, PROBABLY NO MORE
THAN A WEEK, AT MOST.
UH, CAPTAIN, IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY, UH, SAYING,
YOU LOOK AS IF YOU COULD
USE SOME REST.
WE'VE GOT TO
GET THE REPAIRS FINISHED.
WELL, SURELY A FEW HOURS' SLEEP
WOULDN'T --
CONTACT ME IF YOU FIND
ANYTHING ELSE.
IS THERE A PROBLEM, CORPORAL?
NO, MA'AM.
WHY ARE YOU GUARDING
THIS CHAMBER?
CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
LIEUTENANT REED'S REPORT.
WHAT?
YOU REQUESTED A TACTICAL
ANALYSIS OF THE INSECTOID SHIP.
LATER.
ARE WE READY?
JUST A FEW SECONDS, CAPTAIN.
THERE ARE TWO MACOs
POSTED OUTSIDE.
I ASKED MAJOR HAYES
TO ASSIGN THEM.
THESE EGGS ARE VULNERABLE.
THERE ARE BREACHES
IN THE OUTER HULL.
THERE COULD BE PREDATORS AROUND.
ASIDE FROM MICROBES,
WE FOUND NO EVIDENCE OF LIFE
ON THIS PLANET.
TRIP.
WE'RE READY.
START AT 40 MEGAJOULES.
KEEP AN EYE
ON THAT MATRIX CONVERTER.
TAKE IT UP TO 50.
TRIP?
UGH!
SHUT IT DOWN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I -- THERE MUST HAVE BEEN
A SURGE IN THE POWER GRID.
I'LL NEED A FEW MINUTES,
CAPTAIN.
[ SQUEAKING ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD DO.
I'M SORRY.
HOW'S HOSHI COMING
WITH THAT TRANSLATION?
THEIR ICONOGRAPHY IS DIFFERENT
FROM THE OTHER XINDI SPECIES.
IT'S TAKING SOME TIME.
WHEN SHE'S DONE, ASK HER
TO SEARCH THEIR DATABASE.
SEE IF SHE CAN LOCATE ANYTHING
ABOUT THEIR BURIAL RITUALS.
DO YOU PLAN TO HOLD A FUNERAL?
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Tucker to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
I think I figured out
the problem.
Their power grid
can't handle our converters.
IT'S GONNA TAKE AT LEAST THREE
DAYS TO MAKE THEM COMPATIBLE.
WHAT ABOUT THE REACTOR?
ANY WAY TO BRING IT ONLINE?
IT'S POSSIBLE,
BUT THEY LOST MOST OF THEIR
ANTIMATTER IN THE ACCIDENT.
STAND BY.
WORK WITH TRIP.
HELP HIM GET THEIR REACTOR
UP AND RUNNING.
SIR?
WE'RE GONNA TRANSFER
OUR ANTIMATTER TO THEIR SHIP.
USE AS MUCH AS YOU HAVE TO.
OUR RESERVES
ARE AT LESS THAN 60%.
I'M NOT GONNA LET
ANY MORE OF THEM DIE.
TO GET THAT REACTOR
RUNNING AGAIN,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO USE A THIRD
OF OUR ANTIMATTER RESERVES.
WHY SO MUCH?
EVERY SYSTEM ON THAT SHIP
IS INTEGRATED.
THE ONLY WAY TO BRING
BIO-SUPPORT BACK ONLINE
IS TO POWER UP THE WHOLE THING.
WELL, THAT'S NOT GONNA
LEAVE MUCH ANTIMATTER
FOR OUR TORPEDOES,
NEVER MIND OUR ENGINES.
DID YOU INFORM THE CAPTAIN?
I WANTED TO RUN IT
BY BOTH OF YOU FIRST.
I NEVER IMAGINED
CAPTAIN ARCHER
WOULD PUT THE WELFARE OF A FEW
XINDI BEFORE HIS OWN PEOPLE.
DO YOU KNOW HE'S SPENT NEARLY
TWO DAYS IN THAT HATCHERY?
FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
HE HASN'T STOPPED WORKING
LONG ENOUGH TO EVEN SLEEP.
DELAY THE TRANSFER FOR NOW.
THE CAPTAIN GAVE US AN ORDER.
I'LL SPEAK WITH HIM.
WHERE'S TRIP?
DID YOU BRING THE ANTIMATTER?
NO.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
INITIALIZING THEIR REACTOR WILL
DEPLETE OUR RESERVES BY 1/3.
WE CAN SPARE IT.
WE'RE ONLY A FEW LIGHT-YEARS
FROM THE RED GIANT.
WE'LL STILL HAVE MORE
THAN ENOUGH FUEL TO GET THERE.
WE DON'T KNOW FOR CERTAIN
IF THE WEAPON IS IN THAT SYSTEM.
THERE ARE LIVES AT RISK HERE.
BILLIONS OF LIVES ARE AT RISK
ON EARTH IF OUR MISSION FAILS.
I'M WELL AWARE OF THAT.
THESE XINDI ARE INNOCENT.
IF WE LET THEM DIE,
WE'LL BE PROVING TO THE OTHERS
THAT THEY'RE RIGHT ABOUT US.
I DON'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT VULCAN ETHICS,
BUT HUMANS DON'T THROW MORALITY
OUT THE WINDOW
WHEN THINGS START
GETTING A LITTLE ROUGH.
COMMANDER TUCKER AND
LIEUTENANT REED ALSO BELIEVE
THAT THIS WOULD COMPROMISE
OUR MISSION.
YOUR OPINIONS HAVE BEEN NOTED.
NOW GET BACK TO ENTERPRISE AND
START THE ANTIMATTER TRANSFER.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T OBEY THAT ORDER.
YOU MAY NOT BE WEARING
A UNIFORM,
BUT YOU CAN STILL BE CHARGED
WITH INSUBORDINATION.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD
CONTACT STARFLEET
AND DISCUSS THIS
WITH ADMIRAL FORREST.
YOU'RE RELIEVED
AS FIRST OFFICER.
MAJOR, ESCORT T'POL
BACK TO THE SHIP
AND CONFINE HER TO HER QUARTERS.
-SIR?
-I GAVE YOU AN ORDER.
MA'AM.
[ SIGHS ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
[ SIGHS ]
THE FIRST SHUTTLEPOD
IS ON ITS WAY.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
TO TRANSFER THE ANTIMATTER?
USING BOTH SHUTTLEPODS,
ABOUT FOUR OR FIVE HOURS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I DIDN'T REALIZE HOW BADLY
I NEEDED A SHOWER.
I'VE SPENT TOO MUCH TIME
IN THAT HATCHERY.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A NEW FIRST OFFICER,
YOU SHOULD CONSIDER MALCOLM.
YOU'RE GONNA WANT SOMEONE
ON THE BRIDGE FULL-TIME.
I'M A LITTLE BUSY AT THE MOMENT.
I'M HAPPY WITH THE COMMAND
STRUCTURE THE WAY IT IS.
THIS IS ONLY TEMPORARY.
T'POL JUST NEEDED
A SLAP ON THE WRIST.
SHE'S QUESTIONED YOUR ORDERS
LOTS OF TIMES,
BUT YOU'VE NEVER
LOCKED HER UP BEFORE.
YOU HAVE TO ADMIT IT'S
A LITTLE OUT OF THE ORDINARY.
THESE AREN'T
ORDINARY CIRCUMSTANCES.
T'POL REFUSED A DIRECT ORDER
IN FRONT OF THE CREW.
I CAN'T HAVE SENIOR OFFICERS
BEHAVING LIKE THAT,
ESPECIALLY ON A MISSION
THIS IMPORTANT.
MAYBE YOU OUGHT TO CONFINE ME
TO QUARTERS, TOO, SIR,
BECAUSE I'M STILL NOT SURE WE'RE
DOING THE RIGHT THING HERE.
IF THE ROLES WERE REVERSED,
I CAN'T IMAGINE THESE XINDI
WOULD DO THE SAME FOR US.
MY GREAT-GRANDFATHER WAS
IN NORTH AFRICA
DURING THE EUGENICS WARS.
HIS BATTALION WAS EVACUATING
CIVILIANS FROM A WAR ZONE
WHEN THEY CAME UNDER ATTACK.
THERE WAS A SCHOOL
FULL OF CHILDREN
DIRECTLY BETWEEN THEM
AND THE ENEMY.
IF HIS MEN HAD RETURNED FIRE,
THEY MIGHT HAVE HIT IT.
SO HE CALLED THE COMMANDER
ON THE OTHER SIDE
AND GOT HIM TO AGREE
TO HOLD HIS FIRE
LONG ENOUGH TO EVACUATE
THE SCHOOL.
THERE ARE RULES, TRIP,
EVEN IN WAR.
WE HAVE TO HELP THESE CHILDREN.
THIS IS WHAT YOU WANTED
TO SHOW ME?
A BATTLE SIMULATION?
SCENARIOS LIKE THIS
CAN TELL US A LOT
ABOUT THE ENEMY'S
TACTICAL CAPABILITIES,
MUCH MORE THAN WE'D LEARN
FROM A STANDARD ANALYSIS.
I ASKED YOU TO LOOK FOR
WEAKNESSES IN THEIR SHIELDS,
NOT TO PLAY MORE GAMES.
THIS ISN'T EXACTLY A GAME,
LIEUTENANT.
THE SIMULATION FOUND
THAT THEY'RE VULNERABLE HERE.
THEY'VE GOT MINIMAL SHIELDING
AROUND THEIR IMPULSE MANIFOLDS.
A PAIR OF TORPEDOES SHOULD BE
ENOUGH TO TAKE OUT THE ENGINES.
THOSE MANIFOLDS
ARE PRETTY NARROW,
BUT OUR TARGETING SCANNERS
SHOULD BE ABLE TO GET A LOCK.
[ CHUCKLES ]
NICE WORK.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I APOLOGIZE.
I OVERREACTED.
[ SIGHS ] A LOT OF THE CREW'S
ON EDGE LATELY.
THEY CERTAINLY ARE.
I HEARD THINGS GOT
PRETTY UGLY DOWN THERE.
IT'S NOT EVERY DAY I'M ASKED
TO CONFINE A SENIOR OFFICER.
I CAN'T SAY I DISAGREE
WITH THE CAPTAIN'S DECISION.
IF ONE OF MY MEN
DISOBEYED ORDERS,
I'D THROW HIM
IN THE STOCKADE.
YEAH.
WELL, I'VE GOT TO
GET BACK TO THE BRIDGE.
LET ME KNOW IF YOUR SIMULATION
FINDS ANYTHING ELSE.
I'M HERE TO SEE T'POL.
SHE'S NOT SUPPOSED
TO HAVE ANY VISITORS, SIR.
THIS ISN'T A SOCIAL CALL.
I'M HERE FOR
MY NEURO-PRESSURE TREATMENT.
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
YOU DON'T WANT ME TO BRING PHLOX
DOWN HERE, DO YOU?
WHAT'S OUR STATUS?
THE ANTIMATTER'S ON ITS WAY.
I HAD A TALK WITH HIM.
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT.
THIS WHOLE THING WILL BLOW OVER
IN A DAY OR TWO.
OUR ANTIMATTER SUPPLY
WILL BE DEPLETED BY THEN.
THE CAPTAIN'S BEHAVIOR IS
BECOMING INCREASINGLY ILLOGICAL,
EVEN FOR A HUMAN.
HE'S PREOCCUPIED
WITH THE HATCHERY.
HE'S DISPLAYING SIGNS
OF PARANOIA.
I THINK YOU'RE OVERSTATING
THINGS JUST A LITTLE.
YOU CAN'T ALLOW HIM
TO USE OUR ANTIMATTER.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST I DO?
START A MUTINY?
YOU HAVE TO SPEAK WITH PHLOX.
ASK HIM TO RUN A FULL EXAM
ON THE CAPTAIN.
WHAT GOOD WOULD THAT DO?
IF THE DOCTOR CAN FIND
SOMETHING WRONG,
WE MAY HAVE MEDICAL GROUNDS
TO RELIEVE HIM OF COMMAND.
RELIEVE HIM? [ SIGHS ]
LOOK, I KNOW YOU'RE UPSET
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT I THINK YOU'RE
TAKING THIS PERSONALLY.
HOW LONG BEFORE THE REACTOR
IS BROUGHT ONLINE?
ASSUMING HOSHI CAN TRANSLATE
THE INTERFACE...
ABOUT 12 HOURS.
YOU HAVE TO DELAY IT
UNTIL WE CAN VERIFY
THE CAPTAIN'S MENTAL STATE.
IF HE FINDS OUT
WHAT WE'RE DOING,
WE'LL BOTH END UP IN THE BRIG.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO BETRAY HIM.
YOU CAN'T ALLOW YOUR PERSONAL
FEELINGS FOR THE CAPTAIN
TO AFFECT YOUR DECISION.
WE BOTH KNOW HE'S ENDANGERING
THIS SHIP AND OUR MISSION.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WHAT IS IT?
A SUBSPACE VORTEX IS OPENING
OFF THE PORT BOW.
TACTICAL ALERT.
CAPTAIN ARCHER,
REPORT TO THE BRIDGE.
IT'S AN INSECTOID.
THREE BIO-SIGNS ABOARD.
THEY'RE FIRING.
[ EXPLOSION ]
THEY'RE MOVING AWAY
AT FULL IMPULSE.
PURSUIT COURSE.
ARM PHASE CANNONS.
DISABLE THEIR ENGINES.
[ EXPLOSION ]
NO EFFECT.
THEIR MAIN DEFLECTOR'S
CHARGING.
THEY COULD BE
TRYING TO OPEN A VORTEX.
TORPEDOES. MAXIMUM YIELD.
TARGET THEIR
IMPULSE MANIFOLDS.
-READY.
-FIRE.
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON?
AN INSECTOID SHIP, SIR.
YOU DESTROYED THEM?
THEY WERE OPENING A VORTEX.
THEY WOULD HAVE ESCAPED.
THE CREW MIGHT HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO TAKE CARE OF THE HATCHERY.
SIR?
WE COULD HAVE KEPT
OUR ANTIMATTER
AND CONTINUED THE MISSION.
THEY WOULD HAVE
TOLD THEIR SUPERIORS, SIR,
GIVEN AWAY OUR POSITION.
IF YOU'D EXPLAINED TO THEM
WHY WE WERE HERE,
YOU MIGHT HAVE AVOIDED
A FIREFIGHT.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
THEY DIDN'T SEEM PARTICULARLY
INTERESTED IN TALKING.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO MAJOR HAYES.
Go ahead, Captain.
REPORT TO MY READY ROOM
ON THE DOUBLE.
Aye, sir.
I'M RELIEVING YOU
AS TACTICAL OFFICER.
FROM NOW ON, YOU'LL REPORT
TO MAJOR HAYES.
I DID WHAT WAS NECESSARY
TO PROTECT THIS SHIP
AND ITS MISSION.
YOU'LL BE CONFINED TO QUARTERS
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
-CAPTAIN!
-DISMISSED.
YES, SIR.
ARE YOU DONE
WITH THAT TRANSLATION?
ALMOST.
I WANT YOU TO PUT TOGETHER
A DISTRESS CALL
IN THE INSECTOID LANGUAGE.
TRANSMIT IT ON ALL FREQUENCIES
AS SOON AS YOU'RE READY.
UNDERSTOOD.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE IMPORTANT
THAN THE SUCCESS
OF THIS MISSION.
-DO YOU AGREE, MAJOR?
-OF COURSE, SIR.
MY SENIOR OFFICERS
DON'T SEEM TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TRYING TO DO HERE.
I GUESS I HAVE MYSELF TO BLAME.
IN THE PAST, I'VE ENCOURAGED
THEM TO ASK QUESTIONS.
BUT WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR THAT NOW.
I NEED OFFICERS WHO RESPECT
THE CHAIN OF COMMAND
AND CAN FOLLOW ORDERS.
IT WON'T BE A PROBLEM, SIR.
I THOUGHT WHAT HAPPENED
WITH T'POL
MIGHT HAVE BEEN
AN ISOLATED INCIDENT,
BUT I'M NOT SO SURE NOW.
LIEUTENANT REED DESTROYED A SHIP
THAT COULD HAVE HELPED US.
I'M STARTING TO WONDER
IF HE DELIBERATELY TRIED
TO SABOTAGE THIS MISSION.
YOU'RE IN COMMAND
WHILE I'M ON THE SURFACE.
YOU ANSWER TO ME AND ME ALONE.
IS THAT UNDERSTOOD, MAJOR?
PERFECTLY, SIR.
THAT'LL BE ALL.
CAN WE TALK TO YOU
FOR A MINUTE, SIR?
WHAT IS IT?
I'D LIKE YOU TO GO TO SICKBAY
WITH PHLOX.
DO I LOOK SICK TO YOU?
HOSHI SAYS YOU ORDERED HER
TO TRANSMIT A DISTRESS CALL.
[ GRUNTS ] THAT'S RIGHT.
DON'T YOU THINK
THAT'S A LITTLE DANGEROUS?
WE'LL BE LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE
BEFORE THE XINDI RESPOND TO IT.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW FAR AWAY
THEIR SHIPS ARE.
IF WE SEND THAT MESSAGE, WE'LL
BE TAKING A HELL OF A RISK.
WE CAN'T AFFORD
TO PLAY IT SAFE ANYMORE.
THIS MISSION'S TOO IMPORTANT.
THIS MISSION IS TO SAVE EARTH,
NOT AN ALIEN HATCHERY.
CAPTAIN, YOU HAVEN'T EATEN
OR SLEPT IN ALMOST TWO DAYS.
YOU'VE SHOWN SIGNS
OF OBSESSIONAL BEHAVIOR
AND PARANOIA.
IF IT'LL MAKE THE TWO OF YOU
FEEL BETTER,
I'LL GO TO SICKBAY
FOR A COMPLETE PHYSICAL...
AS SOON
AS THAT REACTOR'S ONLINE.
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH, SIR.
PHLOX HAS THE AUTHORITY
TO ORDER YOU TO SICKBAY.
T'POL IS MANIPULATING YOU,
ISN'T SHE?
IF I'M DECLARED UNFIT FOR DUTY,
THEN SHE TAKES OVER.
CAPTAIN, IF YOU WON'T COME
WITH ME, I'LL BE REQUIRED,
UNDER STARFLEET ORDER 104,
SECTION "C,"
TO RELIEVE YOU OF COMMAND.
I EXPECTED SOMETHING
LIKE THIS FROM HER,
BUT NOT FROM THE TWO OF YOU.
CORPORAL.
I'VE ALREADY CONFINED
TWO SENIOR OFFICERS TODAY.
HIS NEUROCHEMISTRY
APPEARS NORMAL.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG WITH HIM?
THIS SCAN IS HARDLY CONCLUSIVE.
I'LL NEED TO GET HIM
INTO THE IMAGING CHAMBER
AND RUN A COMPLETE
NEUROLOGICAL SERIES.
WHEN HOSHI SENDS
THAT DISTRESS CALL,
EVERY XINDI SHIP
THAT PICKS IT UP
WILL START HEADING THIS WAY.
[ SIGHS ]
HE'S GOT HAYES ON THE BRIDGE,
MACOs POSTED ALL OVER THE SHIP.
WHATEVER WE DO,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO DO IT FAST.
WHAT ARE YOU PROPOSING,
COMMANDER?
I THINK IT'S TIME WE TO THROW
THE RULE BOOK OUT THE WINDOW
[ SQUISH ]
CAPTAIN.
I'M SORRY, SIR, NO VISITORS.
AH, YOU LET ME IN BEFORE.
I HAVE NEW ORDERS
FROM MAJOR HAYES.
LOOK, T'POL WAS
A LITTLE ROUGH WITH ME
DURING THE LAST SESSION.
I THINK SHE CAUSED
SOME NERVE DAMAGE.
YOU'LL HAVE TO SPEAK
WITH THE MAJOR, SIR.
THIS IS A STARFLEET SHIP.
I DON'T HAVE TO ASK
MAJOR HAYES FOR ANYTHING.
-STEP AWAY, SIR.
-OH!
STAND DOWN, CORPORAL.
[ GROANS ]
THE CAPTAIN GAVE HAYES
CONTROL OF THE BRIDGE,
POSTED MACOs
ON EVERY DECK.
-IS HE STILL
ON THE SURFACE?
-YEAH.
RETRIEVING HIM
AND THE ANTIMATTER
SHOULD BE THE PRIORITY.
I'D ADVISE SECURING
THE BRIDGE FIRST.
IF HAYES GETS WIND OF THIS,
WE COULD HAVE A FIREFIGHT
ON OUR HANDS.
PERHAPS WE
SHOULD APPROACH THE MAJOR
AND EXPLAIN THE SITUATION.
HE SEEMS LIKE A REASONABLE MAN.
THAT WOULD BE RISKY.
IF HAYES SIDES
WITH THE CAPTAIN,
THIS MUTINY WILL BE OVER
BEFORE IT BEGINS.
WE'LL NEED MORE PEOPLE.
WHO'S ON DUTY
IN THE ARMORY?
ENSIGN WALSH
AND TWO OF MY MEN.
THEY'LL SIDE WITH US, BUT HAYES
POSTED TWO MACOs THERE.
TAKE THE SHUTTLEPOD
BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, SIR?
YOU HEARD ME.
[ GROANS ]
HOLD IT. SORRY.
THAT'S GONNA LEAVE A BRUISE.
-ALL RIGHT.
-YOU'RE WITH ME.
YES, SIR.
WELL, WE WON'T
GET TO THE BRIDGE THIS WAY.
[ ELECTRONIC WHINING ]
[ GROANING ]
CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN, IT'S TRIP!
YOU SHOULDN'T
HAVE WEAPONS IN HERE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
GO AHEAD.
Major, Corporal Chang's
been found unconscious
in T'Pol's quarters.
-WHERE'S T'POL?
-Not here, sir.
HAYES TO THE ARMORY.
ARMORY, RESPOND.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
STAND DOWN!
YOU INTEND TO SHOOT ME,
LIEUTENANT?
TELL THEM TO STAND DOWN.
THE CAPTAIN RELIEVED YOU
OF DUTY...
BOTH OF YOU.
WE DON'T WANT ANYONE INJURED.
PUT DOWN YOUR WEAPONS.
UNTIL THE CAPTAIN
SAYS OTHERWISE,
I GIVE THE ORDERS
ON THIS BRIDGE.
GO BACK TO THE SHIP.
YOU HAVE TO COME WITH US.
CAPTAIN.
SHH. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
CONTACT THE CAPTAIN.
BELAY THAT.
I GAVE YOU
A DIRECT ORDER, ENSIGN.
I'M SORRY, MAJOR.
UGH!
IT'S OVER, MAJOR!
-TAKE HIM TO HIS QUARTERS.
-AYE, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-IT'S COMMANDER TUCKER.
-PUT HIM THROUGH.
-GO AHEAD.
-We've got the captain.
What's going on up there?
THE BRIDGE IS SECURE.
TELL PHLOX TO GET
THE IMAGING CHAMBER READY.
WE'VE GOT A PATIENT FOR HIM.
ACTING CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE RESUMED OUR COURSE
FOR AZATI PRIME.
MAJOR HAYES AND HIS MEN
HAVE BEEN TEMPORARILY
RELIEVED OF DUTY.
DR. PHLOX BELIEVES
HE HAS FOUND AN EXPLANATION
FOR THE CAPTAIN'S BEHAVIOR.
WHERE IS HE?
IN HIS QUARTERS, RESTING.
DO, UH, YOU RECALL WHEN
THE CAPTAIN WAS ATTACKED
BY ONE OF THE EGGS?
IT SPRAYED SOMETHING
IN HIS FACE.
HMM. AND I THOUGHT
IT WAS A DEFENSE REFLEX.
BUT IT WAS ACTUALLY SOMETHING
FAR MORE SOPHISTICATED.
THE SUBSTANCE CONTAINED
A UNIQUE NEUROCHEMICAL.
IT INFILTRATED THE CAPTAIN'S
SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS,
CAUSING HIM
TO, UH, REVERSE-IMPRINT
ON THE BABY INSECTOIDS.
IT'S THE OPPOSITE
OF WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN A YOUNG ANIMAL
BONDS WITH ITS MOTHER.
ARE YOU SAYING HE THOUGHT HE WAS
THE MOTHER OF THOSE EGGS?
WELL, MORE LIKELY,
A CARETAKER.
OF COURSE, THE CAPTAIN
DIDN'T REALIZE THIS
ON A CONSCIOUS LEVEL.
EVENTUALLY, HE BECAME OBSESSED
WITH PROTECTING THE EGGS
TO THE EXCLUSION
OF EVERYTHING ELSE.
INCLUDING OUR MISSION.
I'D LIKE TO SPEAK WITH HIM,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
HE'LL BE AWAKE IN A FEW HOURS.
HE SHOULD BE
FULLY RECOVERED BY THEN.
I WANT YOU AND YOUR MEN
TO RETURN TO DUTY.
YES, MA'AM.
NOT THE SORT OF THING THEY
TRAINED US FOR AT WEST POINT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I IMAGINE NOT.
YOU COULD HAVE COME TO ME,
EXPLAINED THE SITUATION.
WE COULDN'T TAKE THE CHANCE THAT
YOU'D SIDE WITH THE CAPTAIN.
I PROBABLY WOULD HAVE.
YEAH.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
UGH.
DIDN'T MEAN TO WAKE YOU, SIR.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I WAS GETTING UP ANYWAY.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
OH, I'VE BEEN BETTER.
YOU SURE YOU HAD THAT PISTOL
SET TO STUN?
[ SIGHS ] CAPTAIN.
I HOPE YOU UNDERSTAND IF THERE'D
BEEN ANY OTHER WAY --
YOU WERE PROTECTING
OUR MISSION, TRIP.
I WOULD HAVE DONE
THE SAME THING.
STILL, I NEVER THOUGHT I'D FIND
MYSELF POINTING A WEAPON AT YOU,
NO MATTER
WHAT THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
LET'S PUT THIS BEHIND US, OKAY?
YES, SIR.
WHAT'S OUR STATUS?
WE JUST RECOVERED THE LAST
OF OUR ANTIMATTER RESERVES.
THE HATCHLINGS?
PHLOX SAYS THERE'S 19 OF THEM
RUNNING AROUND DOWN THERE.
CHANCES ARE THEY'LL SURVIVE
UNTIL THE NEXT XINDI SHIP
COMES ALONG.
IT'S TIME WE GOT BACK
ON THE ROAD.
I WANT YOU AT YOUR POST.
WE'RE GONNA BE PUSHING
THE ENGINES PRETTY HARD.
I'LL BE ON THE BRIDGE.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO GET SOME REST?
I'VE HAD PLENTY.
I'M SORRY, SIR, BUT THE DOCTOR
WAS INSISTENT.
OKAY.
I GUESS I DON'T WANT
ANOTHER MUTINY ON MY HANDS.
TELL TRAVIS TO SET A COURSE
FOR AZATI PRIME, MAXIMUM WARP.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
[ SIGHS ]