ONE-QUARTER IMPULSE.
THERE APPEARS TO BE
CONSIDERABLE ACTIVITY
AROUND TWO OF THE INNER PLANETS.
NUMEROUS SHIPS, ALL XINDI.
I'M PICKING UP
A LARGE ARRAY OF SATELLITES.
THEY'RE GENERATING
A DETECTION GRID.
DEGRA MENTIONED
A SECURITY NET.
SEEMS LIKE WE'VE COME
TO THE RIGHT PLACE.
THE PLANETOID WE PASSED
ON THE WAY IN --
-PUT US ON THE OTHER SIDE OF IT.
-AYE, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
A CONVOY OF SHIPS IS APPROACHING
THE DETECTION GRID.
LET'S SEE THEM.
MAGNIFY THE LEAD SHIP.
SHOW ME THE WARP SIGNATURE.
DEGRA.
IT MAY SEEM ODD TO CELEBRATE
THE COMPLETION OF A WEAPON,
PARTICULARLY ONE DESIGNED
TO DESTROY
AN ENTIRE PLANET.
BUT RECALL
THE WORDS OF ENARCHIS,
WRITTEN SOME 50 YEARS
INTO THE GREAT DIASPORA --
WITHOUT A WORLD OF OUR OWN,
WE ARE BUT CHILDREN
LOST IN THE WILDERNESS.
ONE DAY WE'LL EMERGE
FROM THIS WILDERNESS,
AND OUR WORK HERE WILL ENSURE
THAT WE'LL NEVER BE LOST AGAIN.
TO A NEW ERA FOR ALL XINDI.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
DEGRA, IT IS GOOD
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
WELCOME.
WHEN CAN WE GET UNDERWAY?
MOMENTARILY. PATIENCE.
PATIENCE IS FOR THE DEAD.
YOU'VE ACCOMPLISHED A GREAT DEAL
IN A VERY SHORT TIME.
WE OWE YOU OUR GRATITUDE.
IT'S TOO EARLY
TO SPEAK OF ACCOMPLISHMENTS.
I'LL RESERVE MY GRATITUDE
FOR WHEN THE HUMANS
HAVE BEEN ANNIHILATED.
I'VE ANALYZED
EVERY LINK IN THE GRID.
I CAN'T FIND
A SINGLE WEAKNESS.
THE GRID IS
EXTREMELY SENSITIVE.
WE'D BE DETECTED
THE INSTANT WE PASS THROUGH.
WE COULD TRY DISABLING IT.
IT UTILIZES
THOUSANDS OF SATELLITES.
IF ONE OF THEM
GOES OUT OF COMMISSION,
IT FILLS THE GAP.
WHAT ABOUT
THE INSECTOID SHUTTLE?
MAKE LIKE ONE OF THE LOCALS?
WE COULD FLY IN,
TRY TO LOCATE WHERE THE WEAPON
IS BEING COMPLETED.
THEIR SHUTTLE
MIGHT BE ABLE TO GET
THROUGH THE GRID
WITHOUT RAISING SUSPICION.
CAPTAIN, WE'RE NOT EXACTLY
EXPERTS AT PILOTING THAT THING.
IT'S GONNA TAKE AT LEAST A
COUPLE HOURS TO GET UP TO SPEED.
TAKE THEM.
I WANT TO LAUNCH
AS SOON AS WE CAN.
[ ENGINE WHOOSHES ]
I THINK I FOUND REVERSE.
GREAT, BUT UNLESS WE PLAN
TO FLY IN ASS-FIRST,
WE'D BETTER FIGURE OUT
HOW TO MAKE IT GO FORWARD.
CAN'T ARGUE WITH THAT.
LET'S CYCLE THROUGH
THESE CONSOLE SETTINGS AGAIN.
UM, TRY THE PORT ACTUATOR.
HERE GOES.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
[ CHITTERING ]
COMMANDER TUCKER
IS GOING TO NEED TIME
TO INSTALL
THE TRANSLATION MATRIX.
IF COMMANDER TUCKER WANTS
TO SPEAK INSECTOID,
I HAVE TO GET THIS RIGHT FIRST.
[ CHITTERING ]
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
THAT WAS "HAVE A NICE DAY,"
OR ITS EQUIVALENT.
JUST GET IN THERE,
FIND THIS THING,
SCAN IT, AND GET OUT.
REMEMBER, WHATEVER INFORMATION
YOU GATHER
WON'T DO US ANY GOOD
UNLESS YOU BRING IT BACK.
WE'LL KEEP THAT IN MIND.
GOOD LUCK.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANKS, CAPTAIN.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
TROUBLE?
IT'S LIKE STEERING AN ASTEROID
RUNNER WITH A BAD AXIS COIL.
THEIR FLIGHT PATH
IS SOMEWHAT ERRATIC.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
OPEN A CHANNEL.
TRIP?
[ GRUNTS ]
SORRY.
NO PROBLEM.
I'LL SEND YOU THE BILL.
I THINK I'M GETTING
A FEEL FOR HER.
SENSORS ARE UP AND RUNNING.
LET'S GET THIS SHOW
ON THE ROAD.
KEEP A SENSOR LOCK
FOR AS LONG AS YOU CAN.
500 METERS.
200.
HERE WE GO.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THEY'RE PASSING
THROUGH THE GRID.
WE'RE IN.
XINDI PATROL SHIP
COMING UP FROM BEHIND.
THEY'RE HAILING US.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
[ CHITTERING ]
DOESN'T EXACTLY SOUND LIKE
"WELCOME TO THE NEIGHBORHOOD."
HOSHI, DON'T FAIL US NOW.
YOUR PRESENCE INSIDE
THE DETECTION GRID
IS UNAUTHORIZED.
EXPLAIN.
WE HAD A SLIGHT
NAVIGATIONAL MALFUNCTION
THAT THREW US OFF COURSE.
IT'S BEEN CORRECTED.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
[ CHITTERING ]
RENDEZVOUS WITH
YOUR CARRIER SHIP IMMEDIATELY.
UNDERSTOOD.
THE DETECTION GRID IS CREATING
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE.
I'VE LOST THEM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
WE'RE BEING SCANNED.
WHERE'S IT COMING FROM?
I'M NOT PICKING UP ANY VESSELS
IN THE VICINITY.
FROM THE MOON'S SURFACE.
A SMALL MONITORING STATION.
THE MOON'S ROTATION
BROUGHT IT IN SCANNING RANGE.
LET'S SEE IT.
MALCOLM?
I'M READING
THREE XINDI BIO-SIGNS.
HAVE THEY SENT OUT
A TRANSMISSION?
NOT YET.
WHAT ARE THEY WAITING FOR?
PROBABLY FOR THE MOON'S ROTATION
TO BRING THEM BACK
INTO COMMUNICATION RANGE.
HOW LONG?
FOUR HOURS.
TARGET THE FACILITY.
LOCK.
SIR.
WE CAN'T RISK IT.
FIRE.
I'M STILL GETTING
TRACE KEMOCITE READINGS,
BUT NOT ENOUGH TO INDICATE
A LARGE-SCALE WEAPON.
THERE'S NOT MUCH LAND
DOWN THERE.
AND WHAT LAND THERE IS
DOESN'T HAVE ANY LIFE ON IT.
TAKE US DOWN, TRAVIS.
CLOSER TO THE SURFACE.
ADJUST 20 DEGREES STARBOARD.
SEE SOMETHING?
I THINK SO.
YOU DID SAY THAT MOST
OF THIS THING'S POWER
WAS ROUTED TO
STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY.
AND YOU SAID WE COULD PROBABLY
FLY IT INSIDE A GAS GIANT.
HELL, IT'S ONLY WATER.
STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY'S HOLDING.
TAKE US DEEPER.
NEGATIVE Z-AXIS, 10 DEGREES.
ARE YOU GETTING
THOSE SCANS, SIR?
THERE'S A LOT OF ACTIVITY
AROUND THE RIGHT
LOWER HEMISPHERE.
I WANT TO HAVE A LOOK INSIDE.
THE CAPTAIN SAID
GET IN AND GET OUT.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT
WE'RE GONNA DO.
AYE, AYE.
IT'S DEFINITELY IN THE FINAL
PHASES OF CONSTRUCTION.
MOST OF THE WORK THAT'S GOING ON
SEEMS MAINTENANCE-RELATED.
I'VE GONE OVER THE SCANS
YOU BROUGHT BACK.
THAT'S THE EXPLOSIVE MATRIX.
IF WE CAN GET CLOSE ENOUGH,
WE CAN SET OFF A CHAIN REACTION
THAT WILL BLOW THIS THING
TO HIGH HEAVEN.
THE INITIAL EXPLOSION WOULD NEED
TO BE OF CONSIDERABLE YIELD.
A COUPLE OF PHOTONIC TORPEDOES
SHOULD DO THE TRICK.
THERE'S ROOM IN THE SHUTTLE.
WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT A ONE-WAY TRIP.
I SHOULD BE THE ONE TO GO.
FORGET IT.
I'M THE ONLY ONE
THAT CAN PILOT THAT SHUTTLE.
I PRACTICED ON THOSE CONTROLS.
I CAN GET HER IN.
-BUT I'VE ACTUALLY DONE IT.
-CAPTAIN.
YOU WANT A SENIOR OFFICER
ON THIS, DON'T YOU?
I'LL BE FLYING THE MISSION.
CAPTAIN?
HOW SOON CAN YOU
GET IT READY?
A COUPLE HOURS TO GET
THE TORPEDOES IN PLACE.
GET STARTED.
MEET ME IN THE LAUNCH BAY
IN 30 MINUTES.
I'M GONNA NEED
SOME FLYING LESSONS.
AYE, SIR.
WELCOME ABOARD, CAPTAIN.
DANIELS.
WHERE AM I?
YOU'RE ON ENTERPRISE --
ENTERPRISE-J, TO BE EXACT,
A DISTANT RELATIVE OF YOUR SHIP.
WE'RE 400 YEARS
IN THE FUTURE.
[ WEAPONS FIRE ]
I'M GOING TO ASSUME YOU BROUGHT
ME HERE FOR A GOOD REASON.
LOOK OUT THERE.
IT EXTENDS 50,000 LIGHT-YEARS
IN ALL DIRECTIONS,
AND IT IS GROWING.
I'VE SEEN IT BEFORE.
I KNOW, IN THE EXPANSE.
YOU KNOW ABOUT
THE ALIEN WE FOUND?
THE TEST SUBJECT?
HE BELONGS TO THE SAME RACE
THAT BUILT THE SPHERES.
THEY'RE ALTERING THIS SPACE
TO MAKE IT HABITABLE
FOR THEIR SPECIES.
IT'S A PRELUDE TO INVASION.
WE CAME TO THE SAME CONCLUSION.
IT'S GETTING HARDER AND HARDER
TO SURPRISE YOU, CAPTAIN.
I'VE BROUGHT YOU TO A MONUMENTAL
EVENT IN HISTORY,
THE BATTLE OF PROCYON V,
WHERE THE FEDERATION
ENGAGED THE SPHERE BUILDERS.
THE FEDERATION?
YOU'VE MENTIONED THEM BEFORE.
VULCANS, ANDORIANS,
ITHENITES, KLINGONS --
DOZENS OF SPECIES,
INCLUDING HUMANS,
ALL UNIFIED
IN A POWERFUL ALLIANCE.
SPHERE BUILDERS.
THE FEDERATION
WINS THE BATTLE.
THEY DRIVE THE ENEMY BACK INTO
THEIR TRANS-DIMENSIONAL REALM.
IF THE FEDERATION HAD LOST,
THE SPHERE BUILDERS WOULD HAVE
SPREAD THROUGHOUT THE GALAXY.
THEY WOULD HAVE
WIPED OUT EVERYTHING.
THIS SPECIES HAS TECHNOLOGY
WHICH ALLOWS THEM TO EXAMINE
ALTERNATE TIMELINES.
THEY'VE SEEN THIS FUTURE,
AND THEY WANT TO
CHANGE THE OUTCOME.
SO THEY CONTACTED THE XINDI
AND CONVINCED THEM THAT HUMANITY
WAS A DANGEROUS THREAT.
THEY WANT THE XINDI
TO DESTROY US.
WITHOUT HUMANITY, THE FEDERATION
WILL NEVER EXIST.
YOU HAVE TO MAKE
THE XINDI UNDERSTAND
THAT HUMANITY
ISN'T THE ENEMY.
IN FACT, IT'S HUMANITY
THAT WILL PROTECT THEM
FROM THE SPHERE BUILDERS
WHEN THIS BATTLE IS WON.
CONTACT THEM. MAKE PEACE.
THEY'RE ABOUT TO DEPLOY
THEIR WEAPON.
I KNOW.
I CAN'T LET THAT HAPPEN.
IF YOU DESTROY THEIR WEAPON,
THEY WILL ONLY BUILD ANOTHER.
YOU ARE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN CONVINCE THEM
OF WHAT I HAVE TOLD YOU.
IT IS CRUCIAL TO HISTORY THAT
YOU DO NOT SACRIFICE YOURSELF.
MY CONCERN IS
WITH PREVENTING THE DEATHS
OF BILLIONS OF PEOPLE.
IF THAT'S
A PROBLEM FOR HISTORY,
THEN HISTORY
WILL HAVE TO SUFFER.
THEN SEND SOMEONE ELSE TO --
I WON'T DO THAT!
CAPTAIN, YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ME.
YOU ARE MAKING
A CATASTROPHIC MISTAKE.
YOU'VE MADE
YOUR SHARE OF MISTAKES.
THIS ISN'T ONE OF THEM.
SEND ME BACK.
SEND ME BACK NOW!
TAKE THIS. IT'S XINDI.
A FAMILY MEDAL THAT BELONGS TO
ONE OF THE CREWMEN ON THIS SHIP.
THERE ARE XINDI SERVING
ABOARD ENTERPRISE-J.
WHY ARE YOU GIVING THIS TO ME?
IN CASE YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND.
I WON'T.
I'LL HAVE THIS QUANTUM-DATED.
WE BOTH KNOW
IT'S FROM THE FUTURE.
WHAT DO YOU INTEND TO DO?
I'M GOING AHEAD
WITH THE MISSION.
YOU DON'T THINK I SHOULD?
HE SAID YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN END THE CONFLICT
WITH THE XINDI.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT
IF YOU'RE DEAD.
THAT'S IF YOU ACCEPT DANIELS'
VERSION OF THE FUTURE.
HE'S IN A POSITION TO KNOW.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
THE SKEPTICAL ONE
WHEN IT CAME TO TIME TRAVEL.
OUR RECENT VISIT TO DETROIT
HAS TEMPERED MY SKEPTICISM.
YOU SHOULD RECONSIDER
YOUR DECISION.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
FLY A SHUTTLE INTO THE SYSTEM
AND KNOCK ON THE DOOR?
TELL THE XINDI
WE WANT TO TALK?
THE WEAPON IS TOO CLOSE
TO BEING LAUNCHED.
IF THE SITUATION
WERE DIFFERENT,
MAYBE I'D CONSIDER IT,
BUT I CAN'T.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO DIE.
IT'S NOT NECESSARY.
I WISH THAT WERE TRUE.
I WANT FOUR SHIPS
TO ACCOMPANY THE WEAPON.
WE'LL HAVE TO GENERATE
AN EXTREMELY LARGE VORTEX
TO ACCOMMODATE
THAT MANY VESSELS.
EVEN AFTER EARTH IS DESTROYED,
THERE WILL BE RESIDUAL PRESENCE
IN THIS SYSTEM.
I INTEND TO HUNT DOWN
AND ERADICATE
EVERY REFUGEE CARAVAN,
EVERY COLONY,
EVERY LAST OUTPOST THEY HAVE.
A VORTEX OF THAT SIZE
WILL BE VERY UNSTABLE.
YOU COULD LOSE
ONE OR MORE VESSELS.
SEE THAT WE DON'T.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
A MESSAGE FOR YOU.
GO AHEAD.
Commander, we've lost contact
with one of the lunar outposts.
-HOW LONG AGO?
-Two hours.
SEND A PATROL.
WE WILL RESUME THIS
WHEN I RETURN.
SOMEONE ONCE SAID
THAT DEALING WITH REPTILIANS
IS LIKE
BARGAINING WITH THE SUN.
YOU MAKE NO PROGRESS,
AND YOU COME AWAY BURNED.
IT'S NOT HIM.
THE LAST TIME I SAW YOU
LIKE THIS WAS
WHEN YOU DELIVERED
THE FIRST WEAPON.
THAT ONE ONLY KILLED 7 MILLION.
THIS ONE WILL DESTROY
AN ENTIRE WORLD.
BETTER THEIR WORLD THAN OURS.
THAT'S WHAT I KEEP
TELLING MYSELF.
BUT THE REALITY IS
A GOOD NUMBER OF THE DEAD
WILL BE INNOCENTS...
AND CHILDREN.
IT'S BEST NOT TO THINK ABOUT IT.
IT'S DIFFICULT WHEN YOU HAVE
CHILDREN OF YOUR OWN.
WHAT WE DO IS FOR THEM,
FOR OUR CHILDREN'S FUTURE.
REMEMBER THAT.
I WONDER HOW
THEY'LL REMEMBER US.
I KNOW THESE CONTROLS
AREN'T EXACTLY INTUITIVE.
I THINK THEY WERE BUILT FOR
SOMEONE WITH COMPOUND EYES.
TRY AGAIN.
[ SIGHS ]
GOOD. YOU'RE STARTING TO THINK
LIKE AN INSECTOID.
I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A COMPLIMENT.
CAN I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
GO AHEAD.
YOU'RE THE LEAST
EXPENDABLE MAN ON ENTERPRISE.
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
AN HOUR AGO, I GAVE THE COMMAND
TO KILL THREE XINDI
IN COLD BLOOD.
A MONTH AGO, I HAD PHLOX
CREATE A LIVING BEING
IN ORDER TO USE
SOME OF ITS TISSUE,
AND I WATCHED HIM
PUT IT TO DEATH.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE SAYING
THIS IS SOME SORT OF PENANCE.
I'M SAYING I WON'T ORDER
ANYONE ELSE TO DIE.
I HATE TO ADD TO THIS MENAGERIE
OF YOURS, DOC.
NONSENSE.
WHAT'S, UH, ONE MORE MOUTH
TO FEED?
JUST DON'T HARVEST
ANY PART OF HIM.
OH...I DOUBT THAT
WOULD BE NECESSARY.
OH, DO ME A FAVOR.
SLIP HIM A PIECE OF CHEESE
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
CERTAINLY.
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN MUCH BETTER
AT AVOIDING FAREWELLS
THAN GIVING THEM,
SO I'M NOT EVEN GONNA TRY.
BUT I'M GOING TO ASK ALL OF YOU
TO THINK BACK
TO THE DAY WHEN THIS SHIP
WAS FIRST LAUNCHED.
WE WERE EXPLORERS THEN.
WHEN ALL THIS IS OVER,
WHEN EARTH IS SAFE,
I WANT YOU TO GET BACK
TO THAT JOB.
THERE ARE 400 BILLION STARS
IN OUR GALAXY.
WE'VE ONLY EXPLORED
A TINY FRACTION.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO DO.
OF ALL THE CAPTAINS
WHO WILL SIT IN THIS CHAIR,
I CAN'T IMAGINE ANY OF THEM
BEING MORE PROUD
THAN I AM RIGHT NOW.
Archer to Enterprise.
I'm heading in.
400 METERS.
200.
HE'S PASSING THROUGH THE GRID.
HE'S IN.
GIVE THEM HELL, CAPTAIN.
I'LL BE IN THE READY ROOM.
[ SOBBING ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
[ CHITTERING ]
UNAUTHORIZED VESSEL,
POWER DOWN IMMEDIATELY.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
[ SIGHS ]
STILL NOTHING.
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
IT'S BEEN OVER TWO HOURS.
HE SHOULD HAVE REACHED
THE WEAPON BY NOW.
TRAVIS AND I GOT THERE
IN 25 MINUTES,
AND WE DIDN'T KNOW
WHERE TO LOOK.
YOU THINK IT'S POSSIBLE
OUR SENSORS
COULD HAVE
MISSED THE EXPLOSION?
DOUBTFUL.
WHATEVER YOU'RE DOING,
CAN'T IT WAIT?
FOR WHAT?
RIGHT NOW...
YOUR PLACE IS ON THE BRIDGE.
I'LL BE NOTIFIED
IF MY PRESENCE IS NEEDED.
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS
TO THE XINDI WEAPON,
THE CAPTAIN ISN'T COMING BACK.
YOU'RE IN COMMAND NOW.
THE CREW NEEDS TO KNOW
YOU'RE ON TOP OF THINGS,
AND IT DOESN'T HELP
IF YOU'RE HOLED UP IN HERE.
I DON'T NEED
ANY LEADERSHIP ADVICE.
I'M JUST TRYING TO HELP.
THIS ISN'T EASY
FOR ANY OF US.
T'POL?
DISMISSED.
DISMISSED?
GET OUT.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
ANSWER THE QUESTION!
AAH. REPEAT THE QUESTION.
HOW MANY EARTH VESSELS
HAVE ENTERED THE EXPANSE?
I WISH I COULD HELP YOU.
[ SPITS ]
BUT MY SUPERIORS KEEP ME IN
THE DARK ABOUT THESE THINGS.
UGH!
IS THIS A PREEMPTIVE STRIKE?
I THOUGHT THAT
WAS YOUR SPECIALTY.
YOU DON'T WANT TO KNOW
MY SPECIALTY.
LET ME GUESS.
STINKING UP THE ROOM?
I HAD NO IDEA THAT HUMANS
WERE SO RESILIENT.
IT'S NOT A TRAIT FOUND
IN MOST PRIMATE SPECIES.
INCLUDING THE XINDI?
THERE'S A REASON REPTILIANS
ARE CALLED UPON
WHEN FORCE MUST BE APPLIED.
IT WAS A REPTILIAN
WHO PILOTED THE WEAPON
THAT ATTACKED YOUR WORLD.
FRIEND OF YOURS?
HE WAS FROM MY REGIMENT.
I SELECTED HIM MYSELF.
YOU MUST BE VERY PROUD.
HIS NAME WILL GO
DOWN IN HISTORY.
IT WILL BE
SPOKEN WITH REVERENCE,
A TESTAMENT TO THE SUPERIORITY
OF THE COLD-BLOODED.
I'LL BET YOU
DIDN'T KNOW THIS,
BUT AT ONE TIME, MOST OF
MY WORLD WAS RULED BY REPTILES.
I WASN'T AWARE OF THAT.
A COMET HIT AROUND
65 MILLION YEARS AGO,
CAUSED A MASS EXTINCTION.
MOST OF THE REPTILES DIED OUT.
MAMMALS BECAME
THE DOMINANT SPECIES.
HOW UNFORTUNATE.
STILL, THE REPTILES MIGHT HAVE
COME OUT ON TOP
IF IT HADN'T BEEN
FOR A SLIGHT DISADVANTAGE.
AND WHAT WAS THAT?
THEY HAD BRAINS
THE SIZE OF A WALNUT.
THAT'S VERY SMALL.
APPARENTLY IT'S A CONSTANT
IN THE UNIVERSE.
EARTH VESSELS -- HOW MANY?
THE REPTILES
DIDN'T ALL DIE OUT.
SOME EVOLVED INTO SNAKES,
ALLIGATORS, TURTLES.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
ONE OF MY FAVORITE RESTAURANTS
IN SAN FRANCISCO
MAKES THE MOST WONDERFUL
TURTLE SOUP.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT SOMETIME
IF YOU'RE EVER IN THE AREA.
[ GRUNTS ]
YOU WANT ME TO KILL YOU?
JUST MAKING CONVERSATION.
RELAYING A FEW
INTERESTING FACTS
ABOUT THE WORLD
YOU'RE TRYING TO DESTROY.
I'LL RECIPROCATE WITH
AN INTERESTING FACT OF MY OWN.
UGH!
WE KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE YOUR SHIP IS.
THAT SO?
WHEN WE LOST CONTACT
WITH OUR LUNAR OUTPOST,
WE SCANNED THE VICINITY
AND DISCOVERED IT...HIDING.
UNLESS YOU TELL ME
EXACTLY WHAT I WANT TO KNOW,
I'LL DISPATCH A SQUADRON
RIGHT NOW.
[ GRUNTING ]
AH. NO MORE CONVERSATION?
HMM?
I HOPE YOU HAD A CHANCE
TO SAY GOODBYE TO YOUR CREW.
ALL RIGHT.
BUT I'LL ONLY TALK TO DEGRA.
DEGRA?
ALONE.
I DON'T KNOW WHO THAT IS.
HE'S BUILDING YOUR WEAPON.
RING A BELL NOW?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK DEGRA
WOULD BE INTERESTED
IN TALKING TO YOU?
JUST TELL HIM
THE NAME OF HIS THIRD CHILD,
TRENIA.
DEGRA HAS ONLY TWO CHILDREN.
PROVE ME WRONG.
TELL HIM.
SENSORS WOULD HAVE
EASILY DETECTED
AN EXPLOSION OF THAT MAGNITUDE,
EVEN UNDERWATER.
I SAY WE GO IN,
GET AS CLOSE AS WE CAN,
AND TRY TO TAKE OUT THE WEAPON.
AGREED.
THIS SYSTEM
IS HEAVILY GUARDED.
OUR CHANCES OF REACHING
THE WEAPON ARE NONEXISTENT.
WE CAN'T JUST SIT HERE.
WHAT DO YOU PROPOSE WE DO?
THERE'S STILL A CHANCE
THE CAPTAIN MAY SUCCEED.
THE LONGER WE WAIT HERE,
THE GREATER THE LIKELIHOOD
WE'LL BE SPOTTED.
IF WE DON'T HEAR FROM
THE CAPTAIN IN ONE HOUR,
I'LL PILOT
A SHUTTLEPOD INTO THE SYSTEM.
-[ SCOFFS ]
-AND DO WHAT?
ATTEMPT A DIPLOMATIC SOLUTION.
YOU'VE GOT TO BE KIDDING.
YOU CAN'T POSSIBLY BELIEVE THAT
THAT HAS ANY CHANCE OF SUCCESS.
THE ODDS AREN'T PROMISING,
BUT THE FACT THAT I'M VULCAN
MAY HELP ME
ESTABLISH A DIALOGUE.
YOU'LL JUST BE
CAPTURED OR KILLED.
PERHAPS.
BUT AT THE MOMENT, I DON'T SEE
AN ALTERNATE COURSE OF ACTION.
HELLO AGAIN.
HOW DO YOU KNOW ME?
LONG STORY.
REPEAT WHAT YOU TOLD HIM.
THE NAME OF YOUR THIRD CHILD
IS TRENIA.
LEAVE ME ALONE WITH HIM.
AND TAKE HIM, AS WELL.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
THREE MONTHS
INTO THE PREGNANCY,
YOUR WIFE CONTRACTED
ANAPROLEAN FEVER.
YOU LOST THE CHILD.
YOU WERE GOING
TO NAME IT TRENIA.
I'VE NEVER TOLD
THAT TO ANYONE.
YOU TOLD IT TO ME.
YOU ALSO TALKED ABOUT
THE WEAPON YOU DESIGNED,
THE ONE THAT KILLED
7 MILLION PEOPLE.
WHEN YOU WATCHED
THE TELEMETRY COME IN,
YOU WONDERED HOW MANY OF THOSE
7 MILLION WERE CHILDREN.
WHO ARE YOU?
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHO I AM
OR HOW I KNOW ALL THIS.
WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS THAT YOU
LISTEN TO WHAT I HAVE TO SAY.
CONTINUE.
[ SIGHS ]
YOUR REASON FOR BUILDING
THIS WEAPON IS BASED ON A LIE.
WHAT LIE WOULD THAT BE?
THAT AT SOME POINT
IN THE FUTURE,
HUMANS ARE GOING TO
DESTROY YOUR SPECIES.
THAT IS NOT A LIE!
YOU KNOW ABOUT THE SPHERES?
OF COURSE.
THEY WERE CONSTRUCTED
BY TRANS-DIMENSIONAL BEINGS.
THEIR PURPOSE IS TO
RECONFIGURE THE EXPANSE
TO MAKE IT HABITABLE
FOR THEIR SPECIES.
THAT'S WHAT DESTROYS
THE XINDI, NOT HUMANITY.
I'VE STUDIED THE SPHERES.
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE TO SUPPORT
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
I'VE SEEN IT HAPPEN.
I'VE BEEN TO THE FUTURE,
400 YEARS INTO THE FUTURE.
YOU EXPECT ME TO BELIEVE THAT?
THERE'S AN ARTIFACT
IN MY RIGHT POCKET.
TAKE IT.
GO AHEAD.
AN INITIATION MEDAL.
HAVE IT QUANTUM-DATED.
THE RESULTS WILL BACK ME UP.
YOU COULD HAVE
GOTTEN IT ANYWHERE.
LISTEN TO ME,
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
IT WASN'T ANY EASIER FOR ME TO
SWALLOW THIS THAN IT IS FOR YOU,
BUT YOU BETTER
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING.
IF YOU DESTROY EARTH,
YOU WON'T JUST BE
ELIMINATING MY SPECIES,
YOU'LL BE ELIMINATING
YOUR OWN.
THE QUANTUM-DATING
CONFIRMS IT.
IT'S FROM THE FUTURE.
THAT DOESN'T PROVE THE HUMAN'S
TELLING THE TRUTH.
IF THERE'S ANY TRUTH
IN WHAT HE'S SAYING,
IT MEANS WE CAN'T TRUST HER.
IT ALSO MEANS
SHE'S BEEN DEALING
WITH THE REPTILIANS SECRETLY.
ARCHER TOLD YOU THIS?
HE SAID HE SAW REPTILIANS
ON EARTH,
IN A PLACE CALLED DETROIT,
OVER 100 YEARS IN THE PAST.
THE PAST?
SO NOW HE'S A TIME TRAVELER?
ACCORDING TO THE HUMAN, THEY
WERE DEVELOPING A BIO-WEAPON.
THE COUNCIL PROHIBITED THAT.
HE SPOKE OF IT
IN GREAT DETAIL.
IF THE REPTILIANS WANTED TO KEEP
THEIR ACTIONS A SECRET,
THE PAST WOULD BE
A GOOD PLACE TO DO IT.
HOW WOULD THEY
GET TO THE PAST?
SHE MAY HAVE TAKEN THEM.
-WE HAVE TO INVESTIGATE THIS.
-THEN, QUICK.
THE WEAPON'S BEEN MOVED
TO A SAFE LOCATION,
BUT IT'S NEARLY READY
TO BE DEPLOYED.
THE COUNCIL MUST BE INFORMED.
REPTILIANS SIT ON THE COUNCIL,
OR HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN?
IF THEY DID GO
BEHIND OUR BACKS,
WE SHOULDN'T REVEAL
WHAT WE'VE LEARNED, NOT YET.
WHAT ABOUT THE AQUATICS?
WE CAN INFORM THEM IN SECRET.
ALL OF THIS COLLUSION
IS DANGEROUS.
THE COUNCIL IS FRACTURING.
WE CAN'T FORGET
WHO THE REAL ENEMY IS.
WE MAY NOT KNOW
WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU FAIL?
ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO JUST KEEP SENDING PEOPLE IN
TILL THERE'S NO ONE LEFT?
THAT'S HARDLY A VIABLE OPTION.
WE ONLY HAVE
ONE MORE SHUTTLEPOD.
YOU'RE MISSING MY POINT.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE DOING
THIS TO MAKE PEACE.
I THINK YOU WANT TO TRY
AND SAVE THE CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE WRONG.
WHY DO I GET THE FEELING YOU
HAVEN'T THOUGHT THIS THROUGH?
YOU HAVE MADE
YOUR OBJECTIONS CLEAR.
NOW RETURN TO THE BRIDGE.
I'M NOT JUST GONNA SIT STILL
AND WATCH YOU FLY OFF AND DIE.
-I GAVE YOU AN ORDER.
-T'POL.
LET GO OF ME!
-I WON'T LET YOU DO THIS.
-I SAID LET GO!
WHAT THE HELL'S
WRONG WITH YOU?
Bridge to T'Pol.
GO AHEAD.
There's no need
to go to the Xindi.
It appears
they're coming to us.
FOUR XINDI VESSELS CLOSING FAST.
HAIL THEM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
NO RESPONSE.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
WHAT EXACTLY
ARE YOU PROPOSING?
THAT WE TRUST EACH OTHER.
YOU WERE CAPTURED
BEHIND THE CONTROLS
OF A SHIP ARMED
WITH EXPLOSIVES.
YOU'RE ASKING FOR OUR TRUST?
YOU'RE BUILDING A WEAPON
THAT COULD DESTROY MY WORLD.
I HAD TO TRY AND STOP YOU.
AND NOW THAT
YOUR MISSION HAS FAILED,
YOU WANT TO NEGOTIATE.
JUST CONSIDER WHAT I SAID.
YOU MAINTAIN THAT
BY DESTROYING YOUR WORLD,
WE'LL BE ENSURING
OUR OWN ANNIHILATION.
THAT'S RIGHT.
BECAUSE IT'S HUMANKIND
THAT ULTIMATELY
SAVES THE XINDI
FROM THESE SPHERE BUILDERS.
WE'RE BOTH FIGHTING
THE WRONG ENEMY.
I'M AFRAID IT'LL TAKE MORE
THAN THIS ANTIQUE
TO CONVINCE US.
QUANTUM-DATING HAS PRODUCED
INACCURATE RESULTS BEFORE.
DO YOU BELIEVE THESE RESULTS
ARE INACCURATE?
LET ME SPEAK TO
THIS COUNCIL OF YOURS,
PRESENT MY CASE.
SOME MEMBERS OF THE COUNCIL
WOULD SOONER EXECUTE YOU
THAN LISTEN.
THEN HELP ME
CHANGE THEIR MINDS.
YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED OURS.
I'VE MADE AN IMPRESSION,
OR YOU WOULDN'T
STILL BE HERE.
UGH!
WE'VE LOST HULL PLATING!
I STILL DON'T HAVE
HELM CONTROL.
T'POL TO ENGINEERING.
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
AAH!
ENGINEERING REPORT.
[ INDISTINCT ]
WE'RE DEAD IN THE WATER.
BRIDGE!
UGH!
COM'S DOWN.
GET IT BACK.
UGH!
OHH!
RESTRAIN HIM.
WE'RE NOT FINISHED.
YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH TIME.
HAS HE REVEALED
THE LOCATION OF HIS FORCES?
WE'VE BEEN
DISCUSSING OTHER MATTERS.
THERE ARE NO OTHER MATTERS.
TAKE THEM BACK
TO THEIR SHIP.
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU CAN'T THREATEN US.
RETURN TO YOUR SHIP.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
HE'S GOING TO A DETENTION CENTER
FOR MORE QUESTIONING.
IF THERE ARE ANY SURVIVORS
FROM HIS SHIP, THEY'LL JOIN HIM.
SURVIVORS?
YOUR SHIP'S UNDER ATTACK.
YOU AGREED TO HOLD OFF!
WE GREW TIRED OF WAITING.
CALL OFF YOUR VESSELS.
I DON'T ANSWER TO YOU.
I'LL ASSEMBLE THE COUNCIL.
BY THE TIME YOU DO,
THE EARTH SHIP WILL BE DUST.
WE'VE GOT HULL BREACHES
ON "C," "D," AND "E."
CLOSE THEM OFF.
THE BULKHEADS
AREN'T RESPONDING!
WE'RE VENTING ATMOSPHERE!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
AAH!
GET HIM TO SICKBAY!
YES, SIR!
TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE!
IF YOU CAN HEAR ME,
I'VE GOT COOLANT LEAKS
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
WE'RE EVACUATING.
[ WHIRRING ]
EVERYBODY OUT!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
AAH!