PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
THIS IS GOING TO HAPPEN TO ME.
IT'S ALREADY STARTED. I CAN FEEL
MY CONTROL SLIPPING AWAY.
WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT A ONE-WAY TRIP.
I'LL BE FLYING THE MISSION.
I WON'T ORDER
ANYONE ELSE TO DIE.
YOU KNOW ABOUT THE SPHERES.
THEY WERE CONSTRUCTED
BY TRANS-DIMENSIONAL BEINGS.
THEIR PURPOSE IS
TO RECONFIGURE THE EXPANSE
TO MAKE IT HABITABLE
FOR THEIR SPECIES.
THAT'S WHAT DESTROYS THE XINDI,
NOT HUMANITY.
WE KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE YOUR SHIP IS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
ANOTHER BREACH ON "C" DECK!
"E" DECK'S DEPRESSURIZING!
WE CAN'T TAKE MUCH MORE OF THIS!
THEY'VE CEASED FIRING.
THEY'RE MOVING OFF...
BACK INTO THE SYSTEM.
ENSIGN, GET US OUT OF HERE.
THRUSTERS ARE DOWN.
I DON'T THINK
WE'RE GOING ANYWHERE.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO RECALL MY SHIPS.
AND YOU HAD NO AUTHORIZATION
TO LAUNCH AN ATTACK.
THE HUMANS
SHOULD'VE BEEN DESTROYED
THE MOMENT THEY WERE DETECTED.
THE COUNCIL DOESN'T AGREE.
YOU'RE PERMITTING AN ENEMY
VESSEL TO REMAIN IN ORBIT
NEAR A MILITARY INSTALLATION!
THEIR SHIP IS
CRITICALLY DAMAGED.
THEY NO LONGER
POSE A THREAT.
THANKS TO AN ATTACK
THAT YOU OPPOSED.
AT THE VERY LEAST,
WE SHOULD BOARD THEIR VESSEL
AND TAKE THEM PRISONER.
IT IS BEING CONSIDERED.
ON THE SUBJECT OF PRISONERS,
THE COUNCIL WANTS ARCHER
FOR FURTHER INTERROGATION.
WE'RE NOT FINISHED WITH HIM.
YOU'VE QUESTIONED HIM
LONG ENOUGH.
HE HASN'T PROVIDED US WITH
THE NECESSARY INFORMATION.
PERHAPS THE COUNCIL
WILL HAVE MORE SUCCESS.
YOU'RE ORDERED TO
RELEASE HIM IMMEDIATELY.
VERY WELL.
WE'VE ARRANGED
FOR HIS TRANSPORT.
WE CAN DELIVER HIM.
HE'S ALREADY BEEN SEVERELY
BEATEN UNDER YOUR CARE.
HE IS THE COMMANDER
OF AN ENEMY VESSEL.
WE NEED ARCHER
IN GOOD CONDITION.
IF HE CAN'T ANSWER QUESTIONS,
WE CAN'T INTERROGATE HIM.
HE WILL NOT BE HARMED
ANY FURTHER.
YOU HAVE MY ASSURANCES.
THAT ISN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
MEANING?
IT WOULDN'T BE THE FIRST OF YOUR
ASSURANCES THAT FELL SHORT.
THE COUNCIL HAS AGREED
THAT THE AQUATICS
WILL TRANSPORT THE PRISONER.
THEY'VE SENT A SHIP.
GET HIM READY.
THE COM SYSTEM'S STILL DOWN,
SO WE DON'T HAVE
A COMPLETE CASUALTY LIST YET.
BUT SO FAR,
THE NEWS ISN'T GOOD.
FIVE PEOPLE ARE CONFIRMED DEAD,
DOZENS WOUNDED.
MOST OF THE HULL BREACHES
HAVE BEEN CONTAINED
WITH EMERGENCY BULKHEADS.
WHAT ABOUT CARGO BAY 2?
I DON'T KNOW.
THERE'S NO WAY TO GET TO IT.
A LARGE PORTION OF "E" DECK
IS STILL DECOMPRESSED.
WEAPONS?
THE AFT TORPEDO LAUNCHER'S
WORKING, BUT THAT'S ABOUT IT.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
I REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S HOLDING US TOGETHER,
BUT LET'S HOPE
IT DOESN'T GIVE OUT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
COMMANDER.
THE PRIMARY WARP COIL'S FRIED.
IT HAS TO BE REBUILT
FROM SCRATCH.
HOW LONG?
A COUPLE OF WEEKS
IF WE HAD THE PARTS. WE DON'T.
AS IT STANDS NOW, WARP DRIVE'S
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
IMPULSE?
I'LL HAVE TO INSPECT THE HULL
AROUND THE EXHAUST MANIFOLDS,
SEE THE DAMAGE FIRSTHAND.
MAKE IT A PRIORITY.
WE'VE HAD A LOT OF INJURIES
DOWN HERE.
IT'LL SPEED THINGS UP IF YOU
ASSIGN ME SOME EXTRA HELP.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ENGINEERING ISN'T THE SAFEST
PLACE TO BE RIGHT NOW.
INDEED. WE'VE ALREADY LOST
ONE CAPTAIN TODAY.
[ GROANING ]
[ LIQUID BUBBLING ]
WHERE ARE YOU TAKING ME?
[ AIR HISSING ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
EMERGENCY POWER'S BACK ONLINE.
WE'LL HAVE PHASE CANNONS
IN ABOUT AN HOUR.
I'D LIKE YOU TO BEGIN REPAIRS
ON "E" DECK.
I'LL HAVE TO PULL PEOPLE
FROM OTHER AREAS.
THERE ARE ENGINEERING COMPONENTS
IN CARGO BAY 2.
THEY'RE CRUCIAL TO
COMMANDER TUCKER'S REPAIRS.
AYE.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
THERE'S A VESSEL APPROACHING.
IT'S XINDI.
AFT TORPEDOES.
TARGETING.
THE VIEWSCREEN?
STILL OFFLINE.
IT APPEARS TO BE
A ONE-MAN VESSEL.
NO ARMAMENTS.
BIO-SIGNS?
ONE.
BRING IT IN.
HERE.
NO INTERNAL INJURIES.
NUMEROUS CONTUSIONS
CONSISTENT WITH BLUNT TRAUMA.
HOW MANY HAVE WE LOST?
14.
3 ARE UNACCOUNTED FOR.
DON'T WASTE TIME ON ME.
IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
DAMAGE REPORT.
WE'LL HAVE IMPULSE POWER
IN SIX HOURS.
AFT TORPEDO LAUNCHERS
AND ONE FORWARD PHASE CANNON
ARE ONLINE.
HAVE HOSHI AND TRAVIS
START ANALYZING THAT POD.
ITS CONFIGURATION
SUGGESTS IT'S AQUATIC.
I WAS ABOARD
ONE OF THEIR SHIPS.
THAT'S THE LAST THING
I REMEMBER.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHY THEY RELEASED YOU?
I THINK I MAY HAVE GOTTEN
THROUGH TO ONE OF THEM.
DEGRA.
[ GROANS ]
THANKS.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
I SHOULD HELP LIEUTENANT REED
WITH HIS REPAIRS.
[ GASPS ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ ELECTRICITY BUZZING ]
[ DISTORTED VOICES ]
[ ECHOING CLINKS ]
[ ECHOING BEEPS ]
THEY WENT TO A LOT OF TROUBLE
TO LET YOU GO.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THEY'LL ATTACK US AGAIN?
THEY'RE NOT EXACTLY UNIFIED.
THE REPTILIANS CAME AFTER US
ON THEIR OWN.
THEY MIGHT DECIDE TO FINISH
WHAT THEY STARTED.
WE'VE RUN OUT OF MOONS
TO HIDE BEHIND,
BUT THERE IS A COMETARY
DUST CLOUD NOT TOO FAR OFF.
T'POL?
THE DIAMAGNETIC FIELDS SHOULD
SHIELD US FROM LONG-RANGE SCANS.
HOW FAR AWAY IS IT?
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Engineering to the bridge.
We just picked up a surge
in the E.P.S. grid on "A" deck.
[ GASPS ]
THANKS FOR THE WARNING.
[ COUGHS ]
HOW FAR?
AT PRESENT SPEED,
ABOUT THREE DAYS.
SET A COURSE.
AYE, SIR.
INSTEAD OF HIDING, SHOULDN'T WE
BE LOOKING FOR THE WEAPON?
SENSORS ARE STILL OFFLINE.
LET'S FOCUS ON GETTING
OURSELVES OPERATIONAL.
WE CAN'T MOUNT A SEARCH WITH THE
SHIP COMING DOWN ON OUR HEADS.
[ SCREECHING ]
I THOUGHT
INSECTOID WAS TOUGH.
ALMOST SOUNDS LIKE MUSIC.
MY MOTHER ALWAYS WANTED ME
TO TAKE PIANO LESSONS.
I SHOULD'VE LISTENED TO HER.
IT'S NEVER TOO LATE.
YOU CAN START
WHEN WE GET HOME.
WE'RE GETTING HOME.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
WE CAN TRUST THIS GUY?
-WHO?
-DEGRA.
HE SEEMS LIKE THE LAST PERSON
WHO'D COME AROUND TO OUR SIDE.
I MEAN,
HE DESIGNED THE WEAPON.
HE MAY NOT BE ON OUR SIDE,
BUT I GET THE FEELING HE'S
STARTING TO QUESTION HIS.
WELL, LET'S HOPE
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I THINK WE'RE READY
TO FIRE THIS UP.
[ ELECTRICITY WHINES ]
[ GASPS ]
MAYBE NOT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
There's an unidentified vessel
approaching.
They're asking
for our assistance.
ANY DETAILS?
Just that they've taken
heavy damage.
JOIN THE CLUB.
HOW LONG TILL THEY GET HERE?
12 minutes.
SET A RENDEZVOUS COURSE.
MAYBE WE CAN HELP EACH OTHER.
THEY HAVE MINIMAL WEAPONS,
ALL POWERED DOWN.
I'M DETECTING NUMEROUS SPATIAL
ANOMALIES IN THE AREA.
CAN YOU GET US THROUGH THEM?
I BELIEVE SO.
HAIL THEM.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
WE'RE RESPONDING TO
YOUR DISTRESS CALL.
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
BUT BE AWARE
THIS REGION CONTAINS
DANGEROUS
SPATIAL DISTORTIONS.
WE'RE RUN INTO THEM BEFORE.
THEY'VE DAMAGED OUR ENGINES
AND LIFE SUPPORT.
WE WOULD APPRECIATE WHATEVER
ASSISTANCE YOU CAN GIVE US.
WE'LL SEE WHAT WE CAN DO.
WHAT BRINGS YOU
TO THIS SYSTEM?
CURIOSITY.
WE'RE STUDYING
THE RED GIANT.
IT'S THE FIRST ONE WE'VE HAD
THE OPPORTUNITY TO EXPLORE.
WE WEREN'T PREPARED
FOR THESE SPATIAL ANOMALIES,
AS YOU CALL THEM.
IT SEEMS YOU WEREN'T, EITHER.
ACTUALLY, THIS IS ALL
THE RESULT OF COMBAT.
COMBAT?
HAVE YOU HEARD OF A SPECIES
CALLED THE XINDI?
NO. WE'RE NEW TO
THIS REGION OF SPACE.
LET'S TALK ABOUT YOUR SHIP.
WE KNOW A WAY TO INSULATE
AGAINST THE ANOMALIES.
THERE'S A SUBSTANCE
CALLED TRELLIUM-D.
I'VE HEARD OF IT.
IT'S EXTREMELY RARE.
I HAVE 60 KILOS
SITTING IN MY CARGO BAY.
WELL, PERHAPS WE CAN WORK OUT
SOME SORT OF TRADE.
THAT'S WHAT I HAD IN MIND.
GIVEN THE CONDITION
OF MY VESSEL,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
WE CAN OFFER YOU.
OUR WARP ENGINE
IS BADLY DAMAGED.
WE COULD PROBABLY SPARE
A FEW PLASMA INJECTORS.
MAYBE SOME ANTIMATTER.
I WAS THINKING MORE ALONG
THE LINES OF A WARP COIL.
I'M AFRAID THAT'S ONE THING
WE CAN'T SPARE.
MAYBE WE CAN MAKE IT
WORTH YOUR WHILE.
WE HAVE CERTAIN TECHNOLOGY THAT
YOU'D PROBABLY FIND USEFUL.
WITHOUT A WARP COIL, THE JOURNEY
BACK TO OUR SYSTEM
WOULD TAKE THREE YEARS.
WE'RE NOT EQUIPPED
FOR A VOYAGE OF THAT LENGTH.
THE XINDI HAVE ALREADY WIPED OUT
7 MILLION OF MY PEOPLE.
NOW THEY'RE BUILDING A WEAPON
TO DESTROY OUR ENTIRE WORLD.
I HAVE TO STOP THEM.
WITHOUT WARP DRIVE,
I WON'T SUCCEED.
I SYMPATHIZE, CAPTAIN.
I WILL HELP YOU
IN ANY OTHER WAY.
BUT I WON'T JEOPARDIZE THE LIVES
OF MY CREW. I'M SORRY.
[ CHOKING ]
[ PANTING ]
AAH!
UGH! OH.
[ AIR HISSING ]
[ GROANING, GASPING ]
THE ESCAPE POD CAN
MANEUVER UNDERWATER.
ASIDE FROM THAT,
NOTHING OUT OF THE ORDINARY.
I'VE GONE THROUGH
THE DATA BANKS --
JUST YOUR STANDARD NAVIGATION
OPERATIONAL FILES.
BUT I DID FIND ONE DOCUMENT --
AN ENGINEER ASKING HIS
SUPERVISORS
FOR ADDITIONAL PARTS.
HERE'S THE TRANSLATION.
THE NAMES OF
THESE SUPERVISORS --
PIRAL, JAINA, TRENIA.
THE NAMES OF DEGRA'S CHILDREN.
I DISCOVERED
A SET OF COORDINATES
EMBEDDED IN THE DOCUMENT.
IT'S NOT A STAR SYSTEM.
THERE WAS ANOTHER
EMBEDDED NUMBER.
A STARDATE, THREE DAYS FROM NOW.
HOW FAR AWAY ARE
THE COORDINATES?
FOUR LIGHT-YEARS.
WE'LL NEED AT LEAST WARP 3
TO MAKE IT IN TIME.
IT'S UNLIKELY THAT DEGRA
WILL WAIT BEYOND THREE DAYS.
HE'S ALL YOURS.
HE WAS THE PERFECT HOUSEGUEST,
AS USUAL.
YOU'LL BE HAPPY TO KNOW
THAT I DISCHARGED
ENSIGN ANSARA THIS MORNING.
AND CORPORAL O'MALLEY
WILL BE RETURNING TO DUTY
THIS AFTERNOON.
CAPTAIN?
HARD TO IMAGINE
THAT WE'LL EVER
GET THIS SHIP
BACK THE WAY IT WAS.
IT'S A SIMPLE MATTER OF REPAIRS.
WELL, PERHAPS NOT THAT SIMPLE.
SOMEHOW, I DON'T THINK
IT'S THE DAMAGE TO ENTERPRISE
THAT'S TROUBLING YOU.
HOW LONG HAVE
YOU BEEN A DOCTOR?
NEARLY 40 YEARS.
AND IN ALL THAT TIME,
DID YOU EVER DO ANYTHING
YOU THOUGHT WAS UNETHICAL?
TWICE. WHY?
I'M ABOUT TO STEP OVER A LINE --
A LINE I THOUGHT
I WOULD NEVER CROSS.
AND GIVEN
THE NATURE OF OUR MISSION,
IT PROBABLY
WON'T BE THE LAST.
PROBABLY NOT.
MAY I ASK WHAT
YOU'RE PLANNING TO DO?
THERE COULD BE MORE CASUALTIES.
I'LL BE READY.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
PUT TOGETHER
AN ARMED BOARDING PARTY.
WHO ARE WE BOARDING, SIR?
THE ALIEN SHIP
WE DOCKED WITH.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WE NEED THEIR WARP COIL.
THEY WON'T GIVE IT TO US, SO
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE IT.
CAPTAIN.
GET YOUR MEN TOGETHER!
WHERE ARE THE OTHER MEMBERS
OF THE COUNCIL?
WE DIDN'T WANT THEM HERE.
WHY?
WE'VE LEARNED SOMETHING ABOUT
THE REPTILIANS THAT CONCERNS US.
THERE'S DISTRUST AMONGST YOU.
YOU CAN HELP ALLEVIATE IT.
CONTINUE.
WE WERE TOLD THE REPTILIANS
ATTEMPTED TO BUILD A BIO-WEAPON.
WHO TOLD YOU THIS?
WE'VE ALSO LEARNED
THAT THEY WERE BUILDING
THIS BIO-WEAPON IN THE PAST
ON EARTH.
AS FAR AS WE'RE AWARE,
REPTILIANS DON'T POSSESS
THE TECHNOLOGY FOR TIME TRAVEL.
YOU WANT TO KNOW
IF THEY HAD MY HELP.
DID THEY?
YES.
AFTER YOU PROHIBITED THEM
FROM CONSTRUCTING
THE BIO-WEAPON,
THE REPTILIANS
AND THE INSECTOIDS
WERE PREPARED TO WITHDRAW
FROM THE COUNCIL.
I ASSISTED THEM SO THE COUNCIL
WOULD REMAIN UNIFIED.
YOU HELPED THEM TO CIRCUMVENT
OUR AUTHORITY.
I PROTECTED YOUR AUTHORITY
BY KEEPING THE COUNCIL INTACT.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE BIO-WEAPON?
IT WAS NEVER COMPLETED,
AND THE THREE REPTILIANS
WERE NEVER FOUND.
YOU CAN'T LOCATE THEM?
THERE ARE LIMITS TO WHAT
WE CAN DO IN YOUR REALM.
IT SEEMS YOU CAN DO
MORE THAN WE THOUGHT.
IS IT TRUE YOUR SPECIES
BUILT THE SPHERES?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU CAN SUBJECT ME
TO THIS INTERROGATION?
IF IT WEREN'T
FOR MY ASSISTANCE,
YOUR SPECIES WOULD
BE FACING DESTRUCTION.
WE'RE GRATEFUL FOR THE HELP
THAT YOU'VE GIVEN US.
THEN PROVE IT.
FOCUS ON THE TASK AT HAND.
THE WEAPON IS NEARLY COMPLETE.
IF YOU PERMIT YOURSELVES
TO BECOME DISTRACTED,
YOU'LL FAIL TO DESTROY
YOUR REAL ENEMY --
THE ENEMY OF ALL XINDI.
DON'T SUMMON ME AGAIN
UNLESS EVERY MEMBER
OF THE COUNCIL IS PRESENT.
I WON'T HELP FUEL
YOUR INTERNAL BICKERING.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE HER.
DO YOU?
WHY SHOULD WE TAKE
ARCHER'S WORD OVER HERS?
BECAUSE ARCHER OFFERED
SOMETHING SHE HASN'T.
PROOF.
UNDER NORMAL CIRCUMSTANCES,
THEY'D BE NO MATCH FOR US.
BUT WE'VE SUSTAINED A LOT
MORE DAMAGE THAN THEY HAVE.
THIS COULD BE RISKY.
ONE LUCKY SHOT TO
OUR STARBOARD NACELLE --
LET'S MAKE SURE THEY DON'T GET
ANY LUCKY SHOTS.
WHY DON'T WE JUST TRANSPORT
THEIR WARP COIL TO ENTERPRISE?
IT'S TIED INTO THEIR
INJECTOR SYSTEM.
IF WE USE THE TRANSPORTER,
WE'D DESTROY THEIR ENGINES.
I'VE GOT TO GET IN THERE,
DECOUPLE IT BY HAND.
HOW LONG?
10 MINUTES, GIVE OR TAKE.
CAN'T TELL FOR SURE
UNTIL I SEE IT.
IF THEY FIGHT BACK,
10 MINUTES COULD BE
A VERY LONG TIME.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD
RECONSIDER NEGOTIATION.
WE CAN'T RISK TIPPING THEM OFF.
WE HAVE TO TAKE THEM
BY SURPRISE.
THAT'LL REDUCE THE LOSSES
ON BOTH SIDES.
WE'LL DISABLE THEIR SHIP
AS QUICKLY AS WE CAN,
BEAM OVER, EXTRACT THE WARP
COIL, AND GET OUT...
HOPEFULLY
WITHOUT ANY CASUALTIES.
SET A COURSE.
-CAN I HAVE A WORD WITH YOU?
-NOT RIGHT NOW.
IF I HAD ANOTHER OPTION,
I'D TAKE IT.
WE'RE NO DIFFERENT THAN
THE MARAUDERS WHO ATTACKED US
WHEN WE ENTERED THE EXPANSE.
WE'RE A LOT DIFFERENT.
BY STEALING THEIR WARP COIL,
WE COULD BE CONDEMNING THEM
TO DEATH.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE THEM
A SUPPLY OF TRELLIUM,
ALONG WITH SOME EXTRA FOOD.
I'M NOT SAYING
IT'LL BE EASY FOR THEM,
BUT THEY'LL STAND A DECENT
CHANCE OF MAKING IT HOME.
YOU'RE FORGETTING THAT WE'RE
IN A DANGEROUS REGION OF SPACE.
OUR ASSAULT COULD CRIPPLE THEIR
ABILITY TO DEFEND THEMSELVES.
NOT IF WE DO IT RIGHT.
AND WHAT IF SOMETHING
GOES WRONG?
WE CAN DEBATE THIS ALL DAY.
I'VE MADE MY DECISION.
"WE CAN'T SAVE HUMANITY
WITHOUT HOLDING ON
TO WHAT MAKES US HUMAN."
THOSE WERE YOUR WORDS TO ME.
I'M NO HAPPIER
DOING THIS THAN YOU ARE,
BUT WE'RE NOT GONNA
MAKE A HABIT OF IT.
ONCE YOU RATIONALIZE
THE FIRST MISSTEP,
IT'S EASY TO FALL INTO
A PATTERN OF BEHAVIOR.
I'M NOT RATIONALIZING ANYTHING.
I KNOW FULL WELL
WHAT I'M DOING.
I CAN'T JUSTIFY
THIS COURSE OF ACTION.
WE DON'T HAVE A CHOICE.
I WON'T LET YOU DO IT!
WE'VE HAD OUR SHARE
OF DISAGREEMENTS...
BUT YOU'VE NEVER TAKEN IT OUT
ON MY DESK BEFORE.
I APOLOGIZE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO YOU?
IT'S BEEN A DIFFICULT FEW DAYS.
I HAVEN'T HAD
THE TIME TO MEDITATE.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD FIND THE TIME.
I DIDN'T MEAN WHAT I SAID.
I'M GLAD TO HEAR IT.
I'LL BE LEADING
THE BOARDING PARTY.
THERE'S NO MARGIN FOR ERROR.
IF WE DON'T DO THIS RIGHT,
PEOPLE ARE GONNA DIE.
I NEED YOU ON THE BRIDGE.
UNDERSTOOD.
-DOCTOR.
-YES, THIS WILL JUST
TAKE A MOMENT.
WHAT IS IT?
THERE'S A GOOD DEAL OF RESIDUAL
TRELLIUM IN YOUR BLOODSTREAM.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN DOING THIS?
THREE MONTHS.
I NEED TO KNOW PRECISELY
WHAT HAS BEEN HAPPENING.
WHEN I WAS EXPOSED
TO TRELLIUM ABOARD THE SELEYA,
IT AFFECTED ME IN A WAY
I WASN'T PREPARED FOR.
AS I RECALL, YOU WERE
HOMICIDAL AND PARANOID.
THE INITIAL EFFECTS WERE...
OVERWHELMING.
BUT AS THEY BEGAN TO WEAR OFF,
I DISCOVERED I WAS ABLE
TO ACCESS CERTAIN...EMOTIONS.
I WANTED MORE.
I BEGAN TO EXPERIMENT
BY INGESTING SMALL AMOUNTS
OF TRELLIUM.
I DEVISED A WAY TO INJECT IT
INTO MY BLOODSTREAM.
YOU MUST HAVE KNOWN
IT WAS DANGEROUS.
TRELLIUM EXPOSURE
IS DEADLY TO VULCANS.
IT EATS AWAY
AT THE NEURAL PATHWAYS.
I THOUGHT, IN SMALL AMOUNTS,
IT WOULD BE SAFE.
AT FIRST, I WAS ABLE TO CONTROL
THE NEW EMOTIONS.
MY INTERACTIONS
WITH THE CREW IMPROVED.
COMMANDER TUCKER, FOR EXAMPLE.
WHEN DID YOU REALIZE
YOU WERE BECOMING ADDICTED?
TWO DAYS AGO.
THE DAMAGE TO "E" DECK
MADE IT IMPOSSIBLE
TO ACCESS THE CARGO BAY.
I BEGAN EXPERIENCING
AGITATION,
ANXIETY,
WITHDRAWAL SYMPTOMS.
YOU'RE NOT
EXPERIENCING THEM NOW?
I WAS ABLE TO RETRIEVE
THE TRELLIUM.
I WAS ALMOST KILLED
IN THE PROCESS.
THIS WILL HELP STABILIZE
YOUR SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS,
BUT THE WITHDRAWAL SYMPTOMS
WILL RETURN IN A FEW DAYS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE TIME.
IT WON'T BE EASY.
I UNDERSTAND.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Archer to T'Pol.
GO AHEAD.
We're approaching the vessel.
Report to the bridge.
I'M ON MY WAY.
YOU SHOULD REMAIN HERE
FOR OBSERVATION.
THE CAPTAIN NEEDS ME.
I HAVE TO GO.
I EXPECT YOU TO REPORT BACK HERE
AT THE FIRST SIGN OF TROUBLE.
ARE YOU GOING TO DISCUSS THIS
WITH THE CAPTAIN?
THIS IS BETWEEN YOU
AND YOUR DOCTOR.
GOOD LUCK.
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE.
STAND BY WEAPONS.
RUN ANOTHER TEST.
IF IT DOESN'T HOLD, WE'LL BYPASS
THE ENTIRE ASSEMBLY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
Sir, there's
a vessel approaching.
It's the Earth ship.
HAVE YOU CONTACTED THEM?
They're not responding.
THEY'RE STILL HAILING US.
200 KILOMETERS.
TARGET THEIR PROPULSION SYSTEMS.
AYE.
FIRE.
THEIR WARP DRIVE'S OFFLINE.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER.
THEY'RE FIRING.
ENERGIZE.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
UGH!
THAT'S THE ACCESS PORT.
STUN GRENADE.
GO!
THEIR WEAPONS ARE AT 50%.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
WE HAVE ANOTHER HULL BREACH
ON "E" DECK.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
OUR PORT THRUSTERS ARE OFFLINE.
WE HAVE TO TAKE OUT
THEIR WEAPONS.
WE CAN'T LEAVE THEM
DEFENSELESS.
IF WE WANT TO GET THROUGH THIS
IN ONE PIECE, WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
THE CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
CLEAR!
UGH!
COVER.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-ARCHER.
-Captain.
WE'VE HIT A LITTLE SNAG.
THEY'RE TARGETING
OUR STARBOARD NACELLE.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
T'POL TO THE CAPTAIN.
GO AHEAD.
WE'RE TAKING HEAVY DAMAGE.
There's a force field
around the warp coil.
TRIP'S TRYING TO DISABLE IT.
TRY IT NOW.
UGH!
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
Go ahead.
PARSON'S BEEN HIT.
LOCK ONTO HER COM SIGNAL
AND BEAM HER OUT OF HERE.
LIEUTENANT.
WE'RE VENTING ATMOSPHERE
ON "C" DECK!
T'POL!
ADJUST PHASE CANNONS
TO A NARROW CONFINEMENT BEAM.
TARGET THIS POWER JUNCTION.
-GOT IT.
-FIRE.
RIGHT THERE.
[ WHIRRING ]
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER.
COMMANDER TUCKER'S ABOARD.
WE HAVE IT.
STAND BY TO BEAM US OUT.
FALL BACK.
WHAT YOU CAN'T HAVE,
YOU TAKE BY FORCE?
WE'VE BEAMED THREE CONTAINERS
OF TRELLIUM
INTO YOUR CARGO HOLD
AS COMPENSATION.
THERE'S ALSO FOOD AND SUPPLIES.
YOU'RE STRANDING US
THREE YEARS FROM HOME.
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
BECAUSE I HAVE NO CHOICE.
ENERGIZE.
I'M NOT SURE WHY I ASKED YOU
TO COME SEE ME.
PERHAPS YOU JUST
NEEDED SOME COMPANY.
PERHAPS.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
I THOUGHT THAT
WITHOUT THE TRELLIUM,
I WOULD NO LONGER
HAVE DIFFICULTY
SUPPRESSING MY EMOTIONS.
BUT THAT'S NOT TRUE.
IT'S NOT SURPRISING THAT
THERE ARE RESIDUAL EFFECTS.
THEY'RE PROBABLY TEMPORARY.
AND IF THEY'RE NOT?
THEN YOU'LL LEARN
TO COPE WITH THEM.
I'M NOT CERTAIN I'LL BE ABLE TO.
I'M...
AFRAID?
VULCANS DON'T EXPERIENCE FEAR.
YOU SOUGHT THESE EMOTIONS.
DON'T EXPECT THEM
TO VANISH OVERNIGHT. PATIENCE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
A FEW TWEAKS,
AND IT FIT RIGHT IN.
-WHAT'S OUR TOP SPEED?
-3.2.
THAT SHOULD GET US TO
THE RENDEZVOUS POINT
WITH TIME TO SPARE.
UGH.
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
SEEMS THE LONGER
WE'RE OUT HERE,
THE MORE I HAVE TO KEEP
SAYING THAT TO MYSELF.
THOSE PEOPLE WILL BE OKAY.
THEY'LL GET HOME.
CAPTAIN TO THE BRIDGE.
Go ahead.
-PREPARE TO GO TO MAXIMUM WARP.
-Aye, sir.