PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
WE DON'T HAVE A COMPLETE
CASUALTY LIST YET.
BUT SO FAR, THE NEWS ISN'T GOOD.
FIVE PEOPLE ARE CONFIRMED DEAD,
DOZENS WOUNDED.
IF YOU DESTROY EARTH,
YOU WON'T JUST BE
ELIMINATING MY SPECIES,
YOU'LL BE ELIMINATING YOUR OWN.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHY THEY RELEASED YOU?
I THINK I MAY HAVE GOTTEN
THROUGH TO ONE OF THEM.
DEGRA.
WE WERE TOLD THE REPTILIANS
ATTEMPTED TO BUILD A BIO-WEAPON.
WHO TOLD YOU THIS?
WE'VE ALSO LEARNED THAT THEY
WERE BUILDING THIS BIO-WEAPON
IN THE PAST ON EARTH.
UGH!
WHEN I WAS EXPOSED TO TRELLIUM,
IT AFFECTED ME IN A WAY
I WASN'T PREPARED FOR.
I DISCOVERED I WAS ABLE
TO ACCESS CERTAIN EMOTIONS.
I WANTED MORE.
I DEVISED A WAY TO INJECT IT
INTO MY BLOODSTREAM.
YOU MUST HAVE KNOWN
IT WAS DANGEROUS.
TRELLIUM EXPOSURE
IS DEADLY TO VULCANS.
ELIZABETH! GET OUT OF THERE!
[ GASPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
WE'RE IN BAD SHAPE.
I CAN'T DENY THAT.
BUT WE'RE STILL
IN ONE PIECE.
ENTERPRISE IS A TOUGH SHIP.
SHE TOOK MORE THAN ANYONE COULD
ASK HER TO, AND THEN SOME.
AND SO HAVE ALL OF YOU.
I WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU.
I ONLY WISH I COULD THANK
THE 18 CREWMEN WHO WERE LOST.
LIKE YOU, THEY UNDERSTOOD
HOW IMPORTANT OUR MISSION IS,
AND THEY ACCEPTED THE RISKS.
WE CAME INTO THE EXPANSE
NOT KNOWING WHAT WE'D FIND,
WITH NO ONE TO RELY ON
BUT OURSELVES.
BUT WE'RE GOING TO SUCCEED,
TO ACCOMPLISH OUR MISSION,
FOR EVERYONE ON EARTH
WHO'S RELYING ON US...
AND FOR THE 18.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
WE MANAGED TO GET INTO
SECTIONS 6 AND 7 ON "C" DECK.
WE FOUND TAYLOR AND KAMATA.
THAT ACCOUNTS FOR EVERYONE.
WHAT'S OUR STATUS ON WEAPONS?
MR. REED HAS BOTH FORWARD
PHASE CANNONS BACK ONLINE
IN ADDITION TO
THE AFT TORPEDO LAUNCHERS.
HULL PLATING IS UP TO 80%.
THAT'LL HAVE TO DO.
WE COULD WAIT,
HANG BACK UNTIL WE'VE HAD
A CHANCE TO MAKE MORE REPAIRS.
DEGRA'S MESSAGE WAS CLEAR.
WE'RE TO MEET HIM
10 HOURS FROM NOW.
AND I DON'T INTEND TO BE LATE.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT
HE'S COUNTING ON.
LURE US INTO AN AMBUSH WHILE
WE'RE STILL LICKING OUR WOUNDS.
I'VE MADE MY DECISION.
WE HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO DO.
I SUGGEST WE GET TO IT.
AYE, SIR.
COMMANDER.
CREWMAN TAYLOR WAS ONE OF YOURS,
WASN'T SHE?
SHE WAS AN E.P.S.
CONTROL SPECIALIST.
DAMN GOOD ONE.
I'D LIKE YOU TO WRITE
A LETTER TO HER FAMILY.
UH...
SHE WORKED ON ROSTOV'S TEAM.
I CAN ASK HIM.
I ASKED YOU.
I'M BARELY HOLDING
THE SHIP TOGETHER.
I DON'T HAVE TIME TO SIT DOWN
AND WRITE A LETTER.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE LONG.
HER FAMILY DESERVES TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO HER.
UNDERSTOOD.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE BUSY. I'LL COME BACK.
AH, AH, AH. HAVE A SEAT.
I'LL HAVE TO USE
A HAND SCANNER.
THE IMAGING CHAMBER
IS STILL OFFLINE.
COMMANDER TUCKER REASSIGNED
THE REPAIR TEAM
THAT WAS WORKING HERE.
HE SAID THE ARMORY
WAS A HIGHER PRIORITY.
WE'LL SEE HOW LOW
A PRIORITY I AM
THE NEXT TIME HE BURNS HIS
FINGERS ON A PLASMA CONDUIT.
AH.
AH. YOU'VE EXPERIENCED
NO FURTHER WITHDRAWAL SYMPTOMS?
NONE.
I'M ONLY DETECTING TRACE AMOUNTS
OF TRELLIUM IN YOUR SYSTEM.
HARDLY WORTH MENTIONING.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
WHAT IS IT?
THESE EMOTIONS...
HAVE GROWN MORE DIFFICULT
TO CONTROL.
MY USUAL TECHNIQUES
FOR SUPPRESSING THEM
HAVEN'T BEEN EFFECTIVE.
ON EARTH, THERE'S A CAUTIONARY
TALE ABOUT THE DANGERS
OF RELEASING A MAGICAL CREATURE
CALLED A GENIE FROM A BOTTLE.
ONCE IT'S OUT, IT'S EXTREMELY
DIFFICULT TO PUT BACK IN.
ARE YOU SAYING THESE EMOTIONS
MAY NEVER SUBSIDE?
YOU USED TRELLIUM
FOR THREE MONTHS.
IT CAUSED SIGNIFICANT DAMAGE
TO YOUR NEURAL PATHWAYS.
YOU MAY HAVE TO LEARN
TO LIVE WITH THESE EMOTIONS.
WE'RE APPROACHING
THE COORDINATES, CAPTAIN.
RIGHT ON SCHEDULE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
NO SHIPS OUT THERE, SIR.
HOSHI?
SCANNING ALL FREQUENCIES.
NOTHING SO FAR.
MAYBE THEY'RE RUNNING LATE.
[ RUMBLING ]
TACTICAL ALERT!
IT'S A SPATIAL ANOMALY.
WE'VE ENTERED A DENSE FIELD.
[ WHOOSHING ]
UGH! TUCKER TO THE BRIDGE.
This is not
the best time for this!
STAND BY, TRIP.
REPORTS OF INJURIES ON "B" DECK.
NO ONE'S OUT THERE, SIR.
GET US OUT OF HERE.
AYE, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE RECEIVING A TRANSMISSION.
IT'S DEGRA.
HE'S TELLING US
TO FOLLOW HIM.
STAY WITH HIM, TRAVIS.
AYE, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THEY'RE HAILING US.
I SEE YOU FOUND MY MESSAGE.
WE HAVE A GREAT DEAL
TO DISCUSS,
AND I DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
COME ABOARD MY SHIP.
IF WE'D LEFT YOU
WITH THE REPTILIANS,
THEY WOULD HAVE KILLED YOU.
DEGRA ARRANGED FOR THE AQUATICS
TO RETURN YOU TO YOUR SHIP.
THEN YOU ALSO CALLED OFF
THE ATTACK ON ENTERPRISE?
THE REPTILIANS WEREN'T VERY
PLEASED ABOUT THAT, EITHER.
YOU'VE TAKEN A BIG RISK.
IF YOU'RE TELLING THE TRUTH,
THE FUTURE OF MY PEOPLE
IS AT STAKE.
EVERYTHING I'VE
TOLD YOU IS TRUE.
FORGIVE ME, BUT THE COUNCIL
WILL NEED MORE THAN YOUR WORD.
PERHAPS YOU CAN DEMONSTRATE
YOUR ABILITY TO TIME TRAVEL.
THAT MIGHT BE A BIT...DIFFICULT.
BUT IF YOU COME ABOARD MY SHIP,
I CAN GIVE YOU
ALL THE PROOF YOU WANT.
VERY WELL.
BUT THERE ARE SOME THINGS
I WANT TO KNOW FIRST.
SUCH AS?
WHEN WILL YOUR WEAPON
BE LAUNCHED?
THE PRECISE DATE HASN'T BEEN
DETERMINED YET.
WEEKS? DAYS?
THAT'S UP TO THE COUNCIL.
I'M TRYING TO HELP YOU,
BUT I NEED TO KNOW MY WORLD
ISN'T BEING DESTROYED
WHILE I'M DOING IT.
THE WEAPON WON'T BE LAUNCHED
FOR SEVERAL DAYS.
SHOW US YOUR PROOF,
AND WE'LL DO
WHAT WE CAN TO STOP IT.
WHAT DID YOU GET?
PEPPERONI PIZZA.
HMM.
DON'T WORRY, YOU CAN
PICK THE PEPPERONI OFF.
DAMAGE REPORTS?
NO.
THE CAPTAIN WANTS ME
TO WRITE A LETTER
TO CREWMAN TAYLOR'S FAMILY.
I'M SURE THEY'LL
APPRECIATE THAT.
THEIR DAUGHTER'S DEAD.
DO YOU REALLY THINK THEY'LL CARE
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY?
[ SIGHS ]
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME YOU SLEPT?
I DON'T KNOW.
NOT SINCE THE ATTACK.
THAT WAS TWO DAYS AGO.
ALL RIGHT, THEN, TWO DAYS.
GO TO YOUR QUARTERS.
GET SOME SLEEP.
BELIEVE ME, I'D LOVE TO.
I COULD ORDER YOU.
I DON'T HAVE TIME.
WE'RE FULL OF HOLES,
THE ONLY THING KEEPING US FLYING
IS A STOLEN WARP COIL,
AND NOW I'VE GOT TO
WRITE THIS LETTER.
[ RUMBLING ]
WHAT THE HELL?
FIRE!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
[ GROANING ]
TUCKER TO ENGINEERING!
SHUT DOWN
THE AUXILIARY COOLANT LINES
BETWEEN SECTIONS, UH,
12 AND 14 ON "E" DECK!
Aye, sir.
TUCKER TO SICK BAY.
MEDICAL EMERGENCY
ON "E" DECK, SECTION 12.
On my way, Commander.
REACTOR PRESSURE'S HOLDING.
GOOD THING
I WASN'T TAKING A NAP.
[ SIGHS ]
DAMRON.
FRIEND OF YOURS?
A COLLEAGUE...OF SORTS.
THEY'RE THE ONES WE FOUND
ON EARTH IN THE PAST.
AND THIS IS THE RESULT
OF YOUR FINDING THEM?
THEY WERE ABOUT TO RELEASE
A BIO-WEAPON
THAT WOULD HAVE
DECIMATED THE POPULATION.
REPTILIANS FELT A TOXIN WOULD BE
MORE EFFECTIVE ON YOUR SPECIES.
DAMRON AND HIS TEAM
DISAPPEARED
SHORTLY AFTER THE COUNCIL
REJECTED HIS PROPOSAL.
APPARENTLY THEY DECIDED
TO GO AHEAD
WITHOUT YOUR COUNCIL'S APPROVAL.
BUT FORTUNATELY,
YOU WERE ABLE TO STOP THEM
BY TRAVELING
BACK THROUGH TIME.
I ALREADY TOLD YOU, WE HAD HELP,
JUST LIKE THEY DID.
THIS PROVES NOTHING.
HOW DO WE KNOW HE DIDN'T CAPTURE
THEM IN THE PRESENT?
YOU NEED MORE EVIDENCE.
THEY HAD THIS WITH THEM.
WE DESTROYED THE TOXIN,
BUT MY DOCTOR KEPT
A SAMPLE OF IT IN STASIS.
THIS APPEARS TO BE
XINDI TECHNOLOGY.
BUT I'D LIKE TO HAVE
OUR ENGINEERS CONFIRM IT.
HAVE THEM COME ABOARD, PERFORM
WHATEVER TEST THEY'D LIKE.
THIS PROVES NOTHING
EXCEPT THE REPTILIANS
DISOBEYED THE COUNCIL,
WHICH COMES
AS NO GREAT SURPRISE.
BUT YOU ALSO CLAIM
THAT WE'VE BEEN MISLED
BY TRANS-DIMENSIONAL ALIENS.
WHERE IS YOUR EVIDENCE OF THAT?
COME WITH ME.
THERE'S A MICROFRACTURE
IN THE MAGNESIUM JACKET.
THAT'S WHY IT RUPTURED.
I RAN A PRESSURE TEST.
TELL IT TO THE MAN
LYING IN SICK BAY!
TEST THEM AGAIN, ALL OF THEM!
AYE, SIR.
COMMANDER?
I'M A LITTLE BUSY, DOC.
SO IT SEEMS.
I UNDERSTAND YOU HAVEN'T SLEPT
SINCE THE ATTACK.
T'POL TATTLING ON ME NOW?
WELL, SHE'S WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
WELL, I APPRECIATE THAT,
BUT I'M TRYING
TO HOLD THIS SHIP TOGETHER
WITH SPIT AND BALING WIRE.
HAS IT OCCURRED TO YOU
THAT WE'LL BE FAR WORSE OFF
IF YOU COLLAPSE
FROM EXHAUSTION?
YOUR CONCERN IS DULY NOTED, DOC,
BUT I GOT TO GET BACK TO WORK.
I DON'T BELIEVE SO.
COME AGAIN?
I'M RELIEVING YOU OF DUTY.
YOU WILL GO TO YOUR QUARTERS
AND NOT RETURN TO YOUR POST
BEFORE 0500 TOMORROW.
SIX HOURS?!
PLEASE DON'T MAKE ME
INVOLVE SECURITY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Archer to Dr. Phlox.
YES, CAPTAIN.
I need you in sick bay.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
WELL, COMMANDER?
I CAN GIVE YOU TWO HOURS.
I BELIEVE THE NUMBER WAS SIX.
IF I'M GONE LONGER THAN THREE,
THERE MAY NOT BE A SHIP HERE
WHEN I GET BACK.
FOUR, NOT A MINUTE LESS.
DONE.
AND REMIND ME TO NEVER BUY
A CAR FROM YOU.
CAPTAIN'S WAITING FOR YOU.
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
WELL, GOOD NIGHT, THEN.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
WE FOUND HIM ADRIFT.
DO YOU RECOGNIZE HIS SPECIES?
WE'VE MET ONE OF THEM.
WHAT CAUSED HIS DEATH?
SOME KIND OF
CELLULAR DEGENERATION.
IT STARTED THE MOMENT
HE WAS TAKEN OFF HIS SHIP.
PERHAPS YOUR ATMOSPHERE
WAS TOXIC TO HIM.
I BELIEVE OUR UNIVERSE
HIS SPECIES EVOLVED
IN A DIFFERENT DIMENSION.
UNDER A DIFFERENT SET
OF PHYSICAL LAWS.
HE SIMPLY COULDN'T EXIST HERE.
THAT'S WHY HIS SPECIES
BUILT THE SPHERES --
TO MAKE OUR SPACE
MORE COMPATIBLE FOR THEMSELVES.
WE BELIEVE HE WAS A TEST SUBJECT
SENT HERE TO SEE
IF THEY WERE SUCCEEDING.
AND IF THEY ARE,
YOU'RE SAYING THE EXPANSE
WILL NO LONGER BE
COMPATIBLE FOR US.
OR ANY OF US.
WE'RE DESTINED TO FORM
AN ALLIANCE TO STOP THEM.
BUT IF YOU DESTROY EARTH,
THAT'LL NEVER HAPPEN.
YOU'LL BE CONDEMNING
YOUR OWN RACE TO EXTINCTION.
[ SIGHS ]
TROUBLE SLEEPING, SIR?
TAYLOR.
YOU WERE KILLED.
THIS WHOLE SECTION DECOMPRESSED.
DID YOU FIND
A SEALED COMPARTMENT?
NO.
THEN HOW...
YOU'RE DEAD.
AND I'M DREAMING.
THE LETTER -- HOW'S IT GOING?
I GOT AS FAR AS...
"I REGRET TO INFORM YOU."
THAT'S A LITTLE DRY, SIR.
YOU'RE NOT REAL.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO CALL ME "SIR."
SO, WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
THE LETTER DOESN'T HAVE
TO BE LONG.
THE CAPTAIN TOLD YOU THAT.
YOU CAN'T THINK OF ANYTHING.
I WISH IT WAS THAT SIMPLE.
I SERVED ON ENTERPRISE
FOR THREE YEARS.
YOU PULLED ME OFF THE SARATOGA
TO BE ON YOUR TEAM.
CAPTAIN BRODY WAS
PRETTY ANGRY AT YOU.
I FORGOT ABOUT THAT.
YOU TOLD ME I'D MAKE
A FINE CHIEF ENGINEER SOMEDAY.
YOU WILL.
YOU WOULD HAVE.
THEN TELL MY PARENTS THAT.
TELL THEM ABOUT THE PRACTICAL
JOKES ROSTOV USED TO PLAY ON ME,
OR THAT ONE TIME I FOUND THE
GLITCH IN THE INJECTOR ASSEMBLY
THAT EVERYONE ELSE MISSED.
TELL THEM HOW HARD I WORKED.
TELL THEM
HOW MUCH YOU LIKED ME.
WHY CAN'T YOU LOOK AT ME?
JUST...REMEMBER ME.
IS THAT ASKING SO MUCH?
YES.
WHY?
[ SIGHS ]
THESE TESTS ONLY CONFIRM
THE EQUIPMENT BELONGED
TO THE REPTILIANS.
THERE'S ALSO EVIDENCE OF
CHRONOMETRIC DISTORTION --
TIME TRAVEL.
THE READINGS COULD
HAVE BEEN FABRICATED.
YOU'RE DETERMINED
NOT TO TRUST HIM.
NO MORE THAN YOU SEEM
TO BE DETERMINED
TO BELIEVE WHATEVER HE SAYS.
NOW, I ADMIT ARCHER'S
EVIDENCE IS INTRIGUING,
BUT WE BARELY KNOW THIS HUMAN.
OUR CONTACT FROM THE FUTURE
HAS HELPED US MANY TIMES.
SHE BROUGHT THIS COUNCIL
TOGETHER.
AND YOU'VE NEVER WONDERED
WHETHER SHE MIGHT HAVE
AN AGENDA OF HER OWN?
I AM NOT A FOOL, DEGRA.
ALL I'M SAYING IS THAT
IT'LL TAKE A LITTLE MORE
THAN A FEW
CHRONOMETRIC DISTORTIONS
TO TURN THE COUNCIL AGAINST HER.
CAPTAIN ARCHER IS EXPECTING ME.
MORE EVIDENCE?
HE CLAIMS TO KNOW A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT THE SPHERES.
DEGRA.
I KNOW YOU'VE HAD DOUBTS
ABOUT BUILDING THE WEAPON.
DON'T LET THEM
CLOUD YOUR JUDGMENT.
WE'VE BEEN WORKING
TO RECONSTRUCT OUR DATABASE.
THE POUNDING YOUR SHIPS
GAVE US DIDN'T HELP MUCH.
TRY IT NOW.
I'M GONNA RESET
THE OPTICAL SUBPROCESSORS.
THAT MIGHT CLEAR IT UP.
WHEN WE SLIPPED THROUGH
YOUR DETECTION GRID,
WE GOT A LOOK AT THE WEAPON
YOU'RE BUILDING.
AN IMPRESSIVE PIECE
OF ENGINEERING.
HELL, IT WOULD TAKE AT LEAST...
A THOUSAND STARSHIPS
LIKE ENTERPRISE
TO BLOW UP AN ENTIRE PLANET.
YOU KNOW, I'D LIKE TO SEE
THE TELEMETRY
FROM THE PROBE
YOU LAUNCHED AGAINST EARTH.
INCREASE THE DATA RESOLUTION.
[ SIGHS ]
I ASSUME YOU WERE
WATCHING THE ATTACK,
CALCULATING THE BLAST YIELDS.
BOY, YOU MUST HAVE BEEN
PRETTY DAMN EXCITED.
I MEAN, THAT BEAM CUT ONE HELL
OF A SWATH THROUGH FLORIDA.
THAT'S THE NAME OF ONE OF
THE PLACES YOU DESTROYED.
FLORIDA.
COMMANDER.
DID YOU ACTUALLY
SEE THE CITIES BURNING,
THE HOUSES,
THE PEOPLE BEING VAPORIZED?
I HAD A SISTER THERE.
COMMANDER!
HOW ARE THE REPAIRS COMING?
JUST NEED A FEW MORE MINUTES,
CAPTAIN.
WHY DON'T YOU JOIN ME
IN MY READY ROOM
UNTIL THEY'RE FINISHED?
LET'S STICK TO THE JOB AT HAND.
AYE, SIR.
THE CAPTAIN IS TRYING
TO GAIN DEGRA'S TRUST.
IT'S ONE
OF THE WARP PLASMA CONDUITS.
IT MUST HAVE RUPTURED
WHEN OUR SENSORS WERE OFFLINE.
PERHAPS MY CREW CAN HELP.
WE'LL HANDLE IT.
WE'LL NEED TO SHUT DOWN
THE MAIN PLASMA FEEDS.
THE FLOW REGULATORS ARE DAMAGED.
THERE ARE MANUAL
CUTOFFS HERE AND HERE,
BUT WE CAN ONLY ACCESS IT
FROM OUTSIDE.
THAT'S VERY CLOSE TO THE FIRE.
WE DON'T HAVE A CHOICE.
IF WE DON'T GET CONTROL
OF IT FAST, IT'LL SPREAD
TO THE REACTOR.
-GET GOING.
-I COULD USE A HAND.
THAT'D BE ME, SIR.
OPEN THAT PANEL,
AND I'LL TALK YOU
THROUGH THE CUTOFF SEQUENCE.
WHERE'S THE OTHER VALVE?
OVER THERE.
[ WHIRRING ]
I NEED TO OPEN THE EMERGENCY
BYPASS PORTS FIRST.
YOU CAN'T CLOSE YOUR VALVE
UNTIL I RELEASE THE PRESSURE
FROM THE SECONDARY LINES.
Commander! I have a problem.
I THINK THE HEAT'S
WARPED THE METAL.
THE PANEL WON'T OPEN.
USE YOUR PLASMA TORCH.
I'LL BE THERE IN A MINUTE.
I'M RELEASING THE INTERLOCKS
ON THE FIRST PORT.
THIS IS GONNA TAKE A WHILE.
Careful you don't cut through
the bypass relays, Malcolm.
THE MANIFOLD PRESSURE
IS INCREASING.
WE HAVE LESS THAN SIX MINUTES
BEFORE THE FIRE REACHES
THE REACTOR SHIELDING.
ARCHER TO TRIP.
You've got less
than six minutes.
UNDERSTOOD.
UGH!
YOU OKAY, MALCOLM?
I'M ALMOST THERE.
CAPTAIN, THE TEMPERATURE
IN LIEUTENANT REED'S SUIT
IS OVER 44 DEGREES.
HE'S TOO CLOSE TO THE FIRE.
HIS E.V. SUIT
CAN'T COMPENSATE.
MALCOLM,
GET BACK TO THE AIRLOCK.
[ SIGHS ]
I'M ALMOST FINISHED, CAPTAIN.
That's an order.
GET INSIDE, MALCOLM.
I CAN WRAP IT UP.
I'M OPENING
THE PRIMARY BYPASS PORT.
TWO MORE TO GO
AND WE'RE IN BUSINESS.
46 DEGREES.
MALCOLM.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
YOU'RE BREAKING UP.
GET INSIDE, MALCOLM.
I CAN FINISH.
THERE'S NO TIME!
DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
SO I CAN SHUT THIS DOWN.
A FEW MORE SECONDS.
I'M PURGING THE LAST PORT.
THE FORWARD VALVE IS CLOSED.
OKAY, MALCOLM,
CLOCKWISE 90 DEGREES.
NICE WORK, MALCOLM.
MALCOLM?
MALCOLM.
TUCKER TO DR. PHLOX.
MEET US IN THE AIRLOCK.
WE NEED TO BRING
HIS BODY TEMPERATURE DOWN.
LET'S GET HIM TO SICK BAY.
I HOPE HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S ONE MORE DEAD HUMAN
TO YOU?
TRIP.
HE HAD NO PROBLEM
KILLING 7 MILLION OF US,
BUT 7 MILLION AND ONE IS
MORE THAN YOU CAN STOMACH?
THAT'S ENOUGH.
I GUESS EVEN XINDI
HAVE THEIR LIMITS.
I SAID THAT'S ENOUGH!
AYE, SIR.
WE'VE DETERMINED
THERE ARE 59 OF THEM.
78, AT OUR LAST COUNT.
78?
WE'VE HAD MORE TIME
TO STUDY THEM THAN YOU HAVE.
I APOLOGIZE FOR MR. TUCKER.
I NEVER EXPECTED TO MEET ANYONE
WHO'D SUFFERED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I'D DONE.
AT THE TIME,
I THOUGHT THE ATTACK WAS
NECESSARY TO SAVE MY PEOPLE.
I KNOW.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, WE'VE HAD
THIS CONVERSATION BEFORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OUR ESCAPE
FROM PRISON TOGETHER.
THE REPTILIANS ARE CORRECT
ABOUT ONE THING, CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE AN IMPRESSIVE FACILITY
FOR DECEPTION.
ERASING YOUR MEMORY
PROBABLY WASN'T THE BEST WAY
TO EARN YOUR TRUST.
PROBABLY NOT.
THEY ARE ALL CONNECTED
BY A SUBSPACE ENERGY GRID.
UNFORTUNATELY, OUR DATA
ON THE SPHERES' INTERIORS
IS EXTREMELY LIMITED.
MAYBE I CAN HELP.
HOW DID YOU GET THIS?
THE FIRST SPHERE
WE CAME ACROSS WAS DAMAGED.
THERE WAS A BREACH
IN THE OUTER SHELL.
WE'VE NEVER BEEN
ABLE TO GAIN ACCESS TO ONE.
THESE SCANS ARE REMARKABLY
DETAILED FOR A MILITARY VESSEL.
ENTERPRISE WAS DESIGNED
TO BE A SHIP OF EXPLORATION.
IF WE'RE SUCCESSFUL,
IT WILL BE AGAIN.
COMPUTER, BEGIN RECORDING.
DEAR MR. AND MRS. TAYLOR,
I REGRET TO INFORM YOU
THAT YOUR DAUGHTER WAS KILLED
IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
SHE WAS A FINE ENGINEER,
AND SHE DIED
PERFORMING HER DUTIES.
COMPUTER, STOP RECORDING.
DELETE THAT.
[ SIGHS ]
COMPUTER, START AGAIN.
DEAR MR. AND MRS. TAYLOR,
AS JANE'S COMMANDING OFFICER,
IT'S WITH DEEPEST REGRET THAT
I INFORM YOU OF HER DEATH.
SHE WAS A DILIGENT ENGINEER,
VERY HARD-WORKING --
Tactical alert.
All hands to stations.
REPORT.
WE'VE DETECTED A SHIP.
THEY'VE JUST PASSED
THROUGH THE CLOAKING BARRIER.
ON SCREEN.
REPTILIANS.
DID YOU INVITE ANYONE ELSE?
WE MASKED OUR WARP TRAIL.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY FOUND US.
WHERE IS DEGRA?
HE'S INVOLVED
IN SENSITIVE NEGOTIATIONS.
WITH THE HUMANS?
I SUPPOSE THE COUNCIL
AUTHORIZED THESE NEGOTIATIONS.
NO ONE AUTHORIZED
THE DEVELOPMENT OF A BIO-WEAPON,
BUT THAT DIDN'T DETER YOUR
COLLEAGUES FROM CREATING ONE.
UNDOCK FROM
THE HUMAN VESSEL IMMEDIATELY.
HE INTENDS TO SEIZE
THE HUMAN VESSEL.
HE'LL DESTROY BOTH OUR SHIPS
IF WE DON'T COMPLY.
-STAND BY.
-DEGRA!
I SAID STAND BY!
WE DON'T STAND
A CHANCE AGAINST THEM,
NOT IN THE SHAPE WE'RE IN.
WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS
DO YOU HAVE?
YOU EXPECT ME TO ATTACK
A REPTILIAN WARSHIP?
IF WE WORK TOGETHER, WE MIGHT
BE ABLE TO DISABLE THEM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
ARE YOU FAMILIAR WITH
THE DESIGN OF THAT SHIP?
I DID SOME WORK
ON THEIR POWER SYSTEMS.
THEN YOU KNOW WHERE
THEY'RE VULNERABLE,
WHERE TO TARGET OUR WEAPONS.
THEIR SHIP IS HEAVILY ARMORED.
AT LEAST WE'D STAND A CHANCE.
THOSE REPTILIANS ARE XINDI.
YOU'RE ASKING ME TO ATTACK
MY OWN PEOPLE.
PROCEED TO OUR
STARBOARD DOCKING PORT.
I WANT YOUR WORD THAT MY CREW
WON'T BE PUNISHED.
YOU'LL ALL BE DEALT WITH
AS THE COUNCIL SEES FIT.
HE'S NEARLY
REACHED THE REPTILIANS.
HE'S KNOCKED OUT
THEIR SHIELD GENERATORS.
FIRE.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
KEEP FIRING.
TARGET THEIR WEAPONS.
THEIR WEAPONS ARE DOWN.
DEGRA WAS SPOT-ON,
KNEW EXACTLY WHERE TO HIT THEM.
OPEN A CHANNEL TO DEGRA.
SIR, HE'S CHARGING WEAPONS!
THE REPTILIAN SHIP
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
CAPTAIN, DEGRA'S HAILING US.
THEY WOULD HAVE CONTACTED
THE COUNCIL
AND EXPOSED OUR ALLIANCE.
I HAD NO CHOICE.
CREWMAN ROSTOV SAID
I'D FIND YOU HERE.
REPAIR CREWS ARE
STARTING TOMORROW.
I THOUGHT I'D TRY
AND GET THEM SOME POWER.
THESE ASSEMBLIES ARE
ALL FUSED TOGETHER.
I'VE SPENT THE LAST HOUR TRYING
TO ISOLATE THE DAMAGED RELAYS.
YOU MIGHT FIND THIS USEFUL.
PORTABLE POWER CELLS.
COURTESY OF OUR
NEW XINDI FRIENDS?
DAMN NEIGHBORLY OF THEM.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN HELP YOU WITH?
NOT UNLESS YOU CAN
RESURRECT THE DEAD.
CREWMAN TAYLOR HAD A REAL KNACK
FOR THIS KIND OF THING.
BUT TAYLOR'S NOT HERE, IS SHE?
AND NEITHER IS CREWMAN KAMATA
OR ENSIGN MARCEL
OR A DOZEN OTHERS,
SO FORGIVE ME IF I DON'T WANT
THE DAMN POWER CELLS!
WE FOUND TAYLOR OVER THERE,
OUTSIDE HER QUARTERS.
SHE WAS PROBABLY TRYING
TO GET TO HER STATION.
IF SHE'D MADE IT
A FEW MORE METERS,
I WOULDN'T BE TRYING TO WRITE
THIS DAMN LETTER,
'CAUSE EVERY TIME I START,
I HEAR MYSELF SAYING
WHAT A FINE
YOUNG WOMAN SHE WAS,
HOW -- HOW SMART
AND FULL OF POTENTIAL.
AND I REALIZE I'M NOT THINKING
ABOUT TAYLOR AT ALL.
I'M THINKING ABOUT ELIZABETH.
THERE'S SO MANY PEOPLE DEAD.
I TRIED NOT TO SEE HER
ANY DIFFERENTLY
THAN THE OTHER 7 MILLION.
SO I'VE SPENT
THE LAST NINE MONTHS
TRYING TO PRETEND
SHE WAS JUST ANOTHER VICTIM.
BUT SHE'S MY SISTER, T'POL.
MY BABY SISTER.
[ SOBBING ]
I ENVY YOU VULCANS.
YOU THINK THAT
THE LOSS OF A COLLEAGUE
OR A FRIEND
DOESN'T AFFECT US?
IT DOES.
BUT IF WE GIVE IN
TO THOSE EMOTIONS,
THEY OVERWHELM US.
YOU'RE THE ONES TO BE ENVIED.
YOU NEED TO SPEAK
TO THE COUNCIL.
WITH THE EVIDENCE
YOU'VE SHOWN ME,
THEY'LL HAVE NO CHOICE
BUT TO TAKE US SERIOUSLY.
EVEN THE REPTILIANS?
I'M MORE CONCERNED
ABOUT THE AQUATICS.
THEY CAN BE SOMEWHAT ENIGMATIC.
BUT IF WE CAN SWAY THEM, WE'LL
HAVE A MAJORITY ON OUR SIDE.
THESE ARE THE COORDINATES
OF THE COUNCIL CHAMBER.
THIS IS NEARLY
A DOZEN LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
IT'LL TAKE US
WEEKS TO GET THERE.
THERE'S A SHORTER ROUTE,
A SUBSPACE CORRIDOR.
IT'S LOCATED IN A NEBULA
LESS THAN HALF A LIGHT-YEAR
FROM HERE.
THAT WILL SHOW YOUR HELMSMAN
HOW TO GET THROUGH IT.
I'LL MEET YOU
AT THE FAR END IN THREE DAYS.
WILL IT BE SOON ENOUGH
TO STOP THE WEAPON?
I'LL DO EVERYTHING
I CAN TO DELAY IT.
USE CAUTION
WHEN YOU ENTER THE NEBULA.
A HOSTILE SPECIES IS KNOWN TO
PREY ON SHIPS THAT APPROACH IT.
THANKS FOR THE WARNING.
SEE YOU IN THREE DAYS.
THREE DAYS.
COMPUTER, BEGIN RECORDING.
MR. AND MRS. TAYLOR,
BY THE TIME YOU GET THIS,
STARFLEET WILL HAVE ALREADY
TOLD YOU ABOUT JANE.
SINCE I WORKED
SO CLOSELY WITH HER,
I WANTED TO ADD
MY PERSONAL CONDOLENCES.
I HAVE TO CONFESS,
I'VE BEEN PUTTING OFF
WRITING THIS FOR A WHILE.
I CONVINCED MYSELF THAT MY
DUTIES ON ENTERPRISE
TOOK PRECEDENCE.
BUT THE TRUTH IS...
I DIDN'T WANT TO FACE THE FACT
THAT SOMEONE SO YOUNG,
WITH SO MUCH PROMISE...
...COULD JUST BE GONE.
BUT I'M FACING IT NOW.
AND I FIND MYSELF THINKING
HOW IMPORTANT SHE WAS TO ME.
SHE WAS A GREAT ENGINEER.
AND SHE WAS MY FRIEND.
SHE WON'T BE FORGOTTEN.
GOODBYE, ELIZABETH.