PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
WE'RE IN BAD SHAPE.
I CAN'T DENY THAT.
PERHAPS MY CREW CAN HELP.
MY EMOTIONS ARE GROWING
MORE DIFFICULT TO CONTROL.
YOU USED TRELLIUM
FOR THREE MONTHS.
YOU MAY HAVE TO LEARN
TO LIVE WITH THESE EMOTIONS.
THESE ARE THE COORDINATES
FOR THE COUNCIL CHAMBER.
IT'LL TAKE US WEEKS
TO GET THERE.
THERE'S A SHORTER ROUTE,
A SUBSPACE CORRIDOR.
I'LL MEET YOU AT THE FAR END
IN THREE DAYS.
SEE YOU IN THREE DAYS.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
THE PROBE?
WE COULDN'T STOP IT
FROM ENTERING THE VORTEX.
IT'S ON ITS WAY TO EARTH.
7 MILLION PEOPLE.
EVERYTHING IS HAPPENING
AS IT DID BEFORE.
THEN YOU HAVE NO CHOICE.
YOU MUST FIND JONATHAN ARCHER.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I'M SORRY TO BOTHER YOU.
I'M HAVING A LITTLE TROUBLE
FALLING ASLEEP.
I THINK MY INSOMNIA'S COME BACK.
YOU'RE HERE FOR NEUROPRESSURE.
IT'S BEEN WEEKS
SINCE OUR LAST SESSION.
WE'VE ALL BEEN UNDER
A LOT OF STRESS LATELY.
THOUGHT IT MIGHT DO US BOTH
SOME GOOD.
I THINK WE SHOULD DISCONTINUE
THESE TREATMENTS.
WHY?
YOU'VE BECOME QUITE SKILLED
WITH THE POSTURES
I'VE SHOWN YOU.
YOU TOLD ME IT TAKES YEARS
TO MASTER NEUROPRESSURE.
I'M NOT THAT QUICK A STUDY.
I'VE TAUGHT YOU ALL I CAN.
LOOK.
TRUTH IS, I'M SLEEPING FINE.
I DIDN'T COME
FOR NEUROPRESSURE.
I CAME BECAUSE
I'M WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
-WORRIED?
-YOU'VE BEEN KEEPING TO YOURSELF
A LOT LATELY,
EVEN MORE THAN USUAL.
YOU SPEND EVERY FREE MOMENT
IN YOUR QUARTERS.
YOU EVEN ASKED CHEF
TO BRING YOUR MEALS HERE.
THE MESS HALL'S HEAVILY DAMAGED.
WHERE DO YOU SUGGEST I EAT?
COME ON.
YOU GOT TO ADMIT
YOU'VE BEEN AVOIDING ME
EVER SINCE THE TWO OF US...
YOU KNOW, WHEN WE...
HAD SEXUAL RELATIONS.
WELL, THAT'S REAL ROMANTIC
WHEN YOU PUT IT THAT WAY.
I TOLD YOU,
WHAT HAPPENED
WAS AN EXPLORATION,
NOT THE PRELUDE TO
AN INTIMATE RELATIONSHIP.
I NEVER SAID
I WANTED A RELATIONSHIP.
NEITHER DID I.
YOU HELPED ME GET THROUGH
A ROUGH PATCH, AND I'M GRATEFUL.
I JUST STOPPED BY TO SEE
IF I COULD RETURN THE FAVOR.
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN.
BUT I'M FINE.
[ SIGHS ]
DEGRA SAID THESE KOVAALANS HAD
ONLY ONE OR TWO SHIPS
INSIDE THE NEBULA.
IT WOULD APPEAR THAT
HIS INFORMATION IS OUT OF DATE.
THERE ARE AT LEAST
HALF A DOZEN SHIPS.
ACCORDING TO DEGRA, THEY'RE NOT
VERY TOLERANT OF TRESPASSERS.
HOW CLOSE ARE THEY
TO THE CORRIDOR?
WITHIN 60,000 KILOMETERS.
WE'LL IONIZE THE HULL.
THAT SHOULD MASK OUR APPROACH
FOR A WHILE.
I SUGGEST WE ENTER HERE,
ABOVE THIS LAYER
OF METREON GAS.
IT SHOULD REFLECT
OUR ENGINE SIGNATURE,
CREATE MULTIPLE SENSOR GHOSTS,
FALSE READINGS.
IF WE'RE LUCKY, THEY WON'T KNOW
WHICH ONE TO FIRE AT.
YOU GAVE THEM THE COORDINATES?
THEY COULD LAUNCH
AN ATTACK AGAINST THE COUNCIL!
ARCHER'S SHIP WAS
HEAVILY DAMAGED.
THEY WOULDN'T STAND A CHANCE
AGAINST ONE OF OUR CRUISERS.
THERE MAY BE OTHER HUMAN SHIPS
IN THE EXPANSE.
THOSE READINGS
WERE NEVER CONFIRMED.
THIS DISCUSSION
IS POINTLESS.
YOU WON'T BE ALLOWED TO BRING
ARCHER BEFORE THE COUNCIL.
THEN WE WON'T ASK
THEIR PERMISSION.
HE'LL BE KILLED
THE MOMENT HE STEPS
INTO THE COUNCIL CHAMBER.
THEY HAVE TO LISTEN.
HIS ALLEGATIONS
ARE TOO IMPORTANT
TO SIMPLY DISMISS.
DO YOU BELIEVE
ARCHER'S BEING TRUTHFUL?
I DON'T THINK
HE'S TOLD US EVERYTHING,
BUT I CAN'T EXPLAIN
THE EVIDENCE THAT WE SAW.
THE HUMANS COULD HAVE
MANUFACTURED THIS EVIDENCE.
THEY'D DO ANYTHING
TO SAVE THEIR PLANET.
IF ARCHER IS
TELLING THE TRUTH,
THEN ALL THE COUNCIL'S EFFORTS
WILL BE FOR NOTHING.
THE REPTILIANS PATROL
THIS SIDE OF THE CORRIDOR
THEY'LL DESTROY THE HUMAN VESSEL
AS SOON AS IT COMES THROUGH.
I'VE ALREADY CONSIDERED THAT.
WE CAN PROTECT THEM.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THE REPTILIANS WON'T FIRE ON US?
TACTICAL ALERT.
TAKE US IN.
AYE, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
A SHIP IS DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
CAN YOU IDENTIFY IT?
THIS CAN'T BE RIGHT.
T'POL?
IT'S STARFLEET, NX-CLASS.
ARE YOU SURE IT'S NOT
A SENSOR REFLECTION?
WE HAVEN'T ENTERED
THE NEBULA YET.
WHOEVER THEY ARE, THEY'RE ON
AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
WE'RE WITHIN VISUAL RANGE.
MUST BE THE NX-02 COLUMBIA.
IT'S STILL UNDER CONSTRUCTION.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S COLUMBIA.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
CAPTAIN ARCHER,
YOU MUST REVERSE COURSE
IMMEDIATELY.
-WHO ARE YOU?
-THERE'S NO TIME TO EXPLAIN.
ALTER YOUR HEADING.
COME ABOUT, ENSIGN.
WOULD YOU TELL ME
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?
YOUR WEAPONS WON'T BE NECESSARY.
I'D LIKE SOME ANSWERS FIRST.
I'M LORIAN,
COMMANDER OF ENTERPRISE.
KARYN ARCHER, MY FIRST OFFICER.
WE SHOULD FIND
A PLACE TO TALK,
PERHAPS THE CONFERENCE ROOM.
YOU'LL WANT T'POL TO JOIN US.
YOU CAN'T TAKE YOUR SHIP
INTO THE SUBSPACE CORRIDOR.
IF YOU DO, IT'LL BE THROWN
BACK IN TIME 117 YEARS.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW THAT?
BECAUSE IT'S ALREADY HAPPENED.
WE'RE HERE TO MAKE CERTAIN THAT
HISTORY DOESN'T REPEAT ITSELF.
THE KOVAALANS
ATTACKED ENTERPRISE
AS SOON AS IT
ENTERED THE NEBULA.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
PHASE CANNONS ARE OFFLINE.
TORPEDOES, FULL SPREAD.
HOW LONG UNTIL WE REACH
THE CORRIDOR?
18 SECONDS.
AFT PLATING'S GONE.
WE'RE LOSING SPEED.
HOLD YOUR COURSE!
THE TRIP THROUGH THE CORRIDOR
TOOK ONLY A FEW SECONDS.
IT DIDN'T TAKE LONG
BEFORE YOUR CREW
REALIZED SOMETHING
WAS WRONG.
NO SIGN OF PURSUIT.
WHERE ARE WE?
WE'VE TRAVELED 11.6 LIGHT-YEARS.
DEGRA?
NOTHING ON LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
CAPTAIN, THE STARS --
THEY'RE NOT WHERE
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE.
ARE YOU SURE WE'RE
AT THE RIGHT COORDINATES?
YES.
ENTERPRISE WAS
IN THE RIGHT PLACE,
BUT IT WAS OVER 100 YEARS EARLY.
WE'RE NOT ENTIRELY SURE
WHY THIS HAPPENED,
BUT WE HAVE A THEORY.
WE THINK YOUR IMPULSE WAKE
DESTABILIZED THE CORRIDOR,
CAUSING IT TO SHIFT IN TIME.
WHY DIDN'T YOU --
DIDN'T WE --
GO BACK THROUGH IT?
T'POL EVENTUALLY DETERMINED
THAT SHIPS CAN ONLY TRAVEL
THROUGH THIS CORRIDOR
IN ONE DIRECTION.
I'LL NOTIFY THE CREW.
LET TRAVIS KNOW
WE'LL BE GETTING UNDER WAY.
WHAT COURSE SHOULD WE SET?
EVEN IF WE COULD FIND A WAY
OUT OF THE EXPANSE,
WE CAN'T GO BACK TO EARTH.
WE'D BE...CONTAMINATING
OUR OWN CULTURE,
OUR OWN HISTORY.
COCHRANE'S WARP FLIGHT WON'T
HAPPEN FOR ANOTHER 26 YEARS.
MAYBE THERE'S A WAY
WE CAN USE THIS
-TO OUR ADVANTAGE.
-HOW?
WE KNOW THE DATE
WHEN EARTH IS ATTACKED
BY THE FIRST XINDI PROBE.
WE MAY BE ABLE TO
FIGURE OUT A WAY
TO WARN THEM
OR EVEN PREVENT THE ATTACK.
THE PROBE WON'T BE DEPLOYED
FOR MORE THAN 100 YEARS.
YOUR CREW REALIZED
IT WOULD BE THEIR DESCENDANTS
WHO'D HAVE TO COMPLETE
THIS MISSION.
IT WAS ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE THE FIRST CHILD WAS BORN.
ENTERPRISE BECAME
A GENERATIONAL SHIP.
YOU SHOWED YOUR CHILDREN
HOW TO OPERATE
AND MAINTAIN ITS SYSTEMS,
AND THEY DID THE SAME
FOR THEIR CHILDREN.
YOU'VE BEEN FLYING AROUND
THE EXPANSE
FOR OVER A CENTURY?
THAT'S UNLIKELY.
ENTERPRISE DOESN'T HAVE
FUEL OR PROVISIONS
FOR SUCH A LONG JOURNEY.
YOU'VE HARDLY CHANGED, MOTHER.
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
YOU MADE ALLIANCES
WITH OTHER SPECIES,
TRADED TECHNOLOGY
FOR FOOD AND SUPPLIES.
YOU EVEN ACQUIRED
A FEW ALIEN CREW MEMBERS.
WE DID OUR BEST TO CARRY OUT
THE MISSION YOU GAVE US,
CAPTAIN.
TO DESTROY
THE FIRST XINDI PROBE.
BUT YOU FAILED.
WE HAD YEARS TO PREPARE,
BUT IN THE END,
WE WERE ONLY ONE STARSHIP.
OUR WEAPONS WERE NO MATCH
FOR THE XINDI.
WE COULDN'T STOP
THE FIRST ATTACK,
BUT WE CAN HELP YOU
STOP THE SECOND.
WE CAN MAKE CERTAIN YOU
REACH THE RENDEZVOUS
WITH DEGRA THIS TIME.
YOU SAID WE COULDN'T TRAVEL
THROUGH THE CORRIDOR.
YOU WON'T NEED TO.
WE'VE ENCOUNTERED
DOZENS OF SPECIES.
SOME OF THEM SHARED THEIR
PROPULSION TECHNOLOGY WITH US.
WE GOT THESE SCHEMATICS
FROM HARADIN TRADERS.
WE CAN USE THEM TO MODIFY
YOUR INJECTOR ASSEMBLY.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO TRAVEL
AT WARP 6.9 FOR BRIEF INTERVALS.
THE HULL WASN'T DESIGNED
FOR THAT SPEED.
WE'LL SHOW YOU HOW TO REINFORCE
STRUCTURAL INTEGRITY.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO REACH DEGRA
IN LESS THAN TWO DAYS.
YOU'VE MADE THESE MODIFICATIONS
ON YOUR OWN SHIP?
OUR PLASMA INJECTORS
ARE TOO OLD.
THEY CAN'T HANDLE THE STRESS.
BUT YOUR INJECTORS
ARE PRACTICALLY NEW.
YOU'RE STILL NOT CONVINCED.
YOU'VE GOT TO ADMIT
IT'S A LOT TO ACCEPT.
WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF TIME.
YOU NEED TO START
THESE MODIFICATIONS.
I'M NOT COMFORTABLE
DOING THAT JUST YET.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD GO
TO SICKBAY.
PHLOX CAN CONFIRM
OUR IDENTITY.
THEY ARE WHO THEY CLAIM TO BE.
MOST OF THE YOUNG WOMAN'S
ANCESTORS WERE HUMAN,
BUT THERE ARE ALSO CHROMOSOMES
FROM THREE SPECIES
I'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
THESE GENETIC MARKERS
BELONG TO YOU, CAPTAIN.
SHE WOULD APPEAR TO BE
YOUR GREAT-GRANDDAUGHTER.
I'VE COMPARED YOUR GENETIC
PROFILE WITH LORIAN'S.
THESE BASE-PAIR SEQUENCES COULD
ONLY HAVE COME FROM YOU.
-THESE CHROMOSOMES ARE HUMAN.
-THAT'S CORRECT.
THEY, UH, CAME
FROM HIS FATHER.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
HUMANS AND VULCANS HAVE NEVER
BEEN ABLE TO REPRODUCE.
ACCORDING TO LORIAN,
I DISCOVERED --
OR RATHER, I WILL DISCOVER --
A METHOD
OF SUCCESSFULLY COMBINING
HUMAN AND VULCAN GENOMES.
WHO'S THE FATHER?
COMMANDER TUCKER.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
I'VE DECIDED TO PROCEED
WITH LORIAN'S PLAN
TO MODIFY OUR WARP ENGINES.
BOTH SHIPS HAVE MOVED
A SAFE DISTANCE FROM THE NEBULA
TO AVOID CONFLICT
WITH THE KOVAALANS.
IT'S THE STRANGEST THING.
I, UH --
I LOOK AT YOU,
AND I SEE MY FATHER.
RIGHT HERE, AROUND THE EYES.
NOW, THE EARS -- THOSE --
THOSE ARE YOUR MOTHER'S.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WAIT A MINUTE,
YOU -- YOU SMILED.
I WASN'T RAISED WITH THE SAME
INHIBITIONS MOST VULCANS HAVE.
MY HUMAN SIDE HAS ALLOWED ME
TO FIND A BALANCE
BETWEEN EMOTION AND LOGIC.
I'VE EVEN BEEN KNOWN
TO TELL A JOKE ON OCCASION.
WOULD YOU HAND ME
THE COIL SPANNER?
I LEARNED ALMOST
EVERYTHING I KNOW
BY STUDYING YOUR
ENGINEERING LOGS.
PRETTY DRY READING.
I HOPE I GAVE YOU SOME HANDS-ON
TRAINING AS WELL.
I'M SURE YOU WOULD HAVE.
YOU SHOULD REINITIALIZE
THE STARTUP ROUTINE
BEFORE GOING TO WARP 6.
THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU'RE NOT TELLING ME.
YOU DIED WHEN I WAS 14.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I'M NOT SURE WE SHOULD BE
DISCUSSING THE FUTURE.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN EASY
GROWING UP
WITHOUT THE OLD MAN AROUND.
SORRY I WASN'T THERE.
YOU WERE A GOOD FATHER.
IT'S STRANGE BEING ABLE
TO TELL YOU THAT.
WE'VE DOUBLED THE EFFICIENCY
OF OUR ATMOSPHERE PROCESSORS.
WE CAN GIVE YOU
THOSE SPECS, TOO.
THANKS.
STARFLEET WILL BE GLAD TO HEAR
ENTERPRISE WAS BUILT TO LAST.
COME ON. UH-OH!
OH!
THANKS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WASN'T THAT BOY DENOBULAN?
MANY OF OUR CREW ARE
DESCENDANTS OF PHLOX.
HE AND AMANDA HAD NINE CHILDREN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU'RE NOT
ENTIRELY HUMAN YOURSELF.
MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER
WAS IKAARAN.
WHO'S THAT?
YOUR WIFE.
HER NAME WAS ESILIA.
YOU RESCUED HER SHIP
FROM AN ANOMALY FIELD.
YOU KNOW, FINDING YOUR SHIP
EXPLAINS A FEW THINGS.
WHEN THE XINDI
TOOK ME PRISONER,
THEY ASKED ME ONE QUESTION
OVER AND OVER.
THEY WANTED TO KNOW
HOW MANY SHIPS
STARFLEET HAD IN THE EXPANSE.
I'M SURE THEY'VE PICKED US UP
ON THEIR SENSORS MORE THAN ONCE.
I THOUGHT WE WERE
GOING TO THE BRIDGE.
THERE'S SOMEONE
WHO'D LIKE TO SEE YOU FIRST.
HELLO, JONATHAN.
T'POL.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
LIVING WITH HUMANS
FOR SO LONG HAS CHANGED YOU.
THEY DIDN'T TELL ME
YOU WERE STILL ABOARD.
AH.
YOU MEAN STILL ALIVE.
YOU LOOK WELL.
HOW'S TRIP?
HE'S FINE.
IF YOU'D LIKE, I'LL HAVE HIM
COME BY AND SAY HELLO.
THAT MIGHT BE AWKWARD.
THERE'S SO MUCH
I WANT TO ASK YOU.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE TO START.
I WISH WE HAD TIME
TO GET REACQUAINTED.
YOU MUST GIVE THIS
TO YOUR SCIENCE OFFICER.
SHE'LL KNOW WHAT IT MEANS.
TWO. A BOY AND A GIRL.
TORU AND YOSHIKO.
WHO'S THE FATHER?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS PROBABLY
IN THEIR DATABASE,
BUT I DIDN'T LOOK IT UP.
WHY NOT?
YOU GOT TO BE CURIOUS.
SOME THINGS ARE
BETTER LEFT A MYSTERY.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
DID YOU GET MARRIED?
CORPORAL McKENZIE.
A MACO?
HOW WELL DO YOU KNOW HER?
WE TALKED AFTER
A TRAINING SESSION ONCE.
YEAH? YOU SHOULD ASK HER OUT.
IS THIS TAKEN?
PLEASE.
SO, LIEUTENANT,
WHO'D YOU END UP WITH
ON THE OTHER ENTERPRISE?
DID YOU GET MARRIED, HAVE KIDS?
UH, NO.
ACTUALLY, I DIDN'T.
APPARENTLY, THE REED FAMILY LINE
CAME TO A RATHER
UNCEREMONIOUS END.
YOU'D THINK ON
A SHIP QUITE THIS SIZE,
I WOULD'VE BEEN ABLE
TO FIND SOMEONE, BUT...
WOMEN ONLY MAKE UP
A THIRD OF THE CREW.
THERE WERE BOUND TO BE
A FEW BACHELORS LEFT OVER.
YEAH.
AND IT WOULD APPEAR
I'M GOING TO BE ONE OF THEM.
I'M ON DUTY IN A FEW MINUTES.
ME TOO.
SEE YOU LATER, SIR.
YEAH.
[ SIGHS ]
THIS SEAT'S AVAILABLE.
SHE THINKS THAT
LORIAN'S PLAN WON'T WORK.
T'POL FOUND A DISCREPANCY
IN HIS CALCULATIONS.
IF WE EXCEED WARP 5.6,
THE INJECTORS COULD
START TO OVERLOAD.
WE'D BE DESTROYED.
HAVE YOU SHOWN THAT TO TRIP?
HE AGREES WITH THE ASSESSMENT.
WE'LL HAVE TO CONTACT DEGRA,
TELL HIM WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO MAKE THE RENDEZVOUS.
THERE IS AN ALTERNATIVE.
THE SUBSPACE CORRIDOR.
WE'LL BE THROWN BACK IN TIME.
NOT NECESSARILY.
T'POL SPENT MANY YEARS
EXAMINING THEIR SENSOR LOGS
FROM THE INCIDENT.
SHE BELIEVES IT'S POSSIBLE
TO RECONFIGURE
OUR IMPULSE MANIFOLDS.
IT SHOULD PREVENT THE CORRIDOR
FROM DESTABILIZING.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE?
ABOUT 12 HOURS.
YOU SHOULD HAVE TOLD ME.
MY SHIP COULD BE DESTROYED.
THERE'S ONLY A 22% CHANCE
OF AN OVERLOAD.
I'D CALL THAT A DAMN BIG RISK.
THERE'S NO ALTERNATIVE.
YOU'LL BE THROWN INTO THE PAST
IF YOU TRY TO USE THE CORRIDOR.
I'VE GOT TWO T'POLS
WHO DISAGREE WITH YOU.
THE KOVAALANS
WILL ATTACK ENTERPRISE
THE MOMENT IT ENTERS THE NEBULA.
IF THEY DAMAGE YOUR MANIFOLDS,
THE CORRIDOR WILL
DESTABILIZE AGAIN.
IT'S OUR BEST OPTION.
YOU HAVE TO LISTEN TO ME.
THIS IS MY MISSION
AND MY DECISION!
SAVING EARTH IS MY MISSION
AS MUCH AS YOURS.
I DIDN'T COME OVER HERE
FOR A DEBATE.
I'VE ALREADY GIVEN THE ORDER.
TRIP'S SHORTHANDED
IN ENGINEERING.
IF YOU COULD
SPARE A FEW PEOPLE,
HE COULD GET
THE WORK DONE FASTER.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
SPOKEN TO ARCHER.
HE HAD ALL THE RIGHT
TO KNOW THE RISKS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL HIM?
IF THEY USE THAT CORRIDOR,
THEIR MISSION WILL FAIL.
EARTH WILL BE DESTROYED.
YOU'RE ALLOWING YOUR HUMAN SIDE
TO GET THE BETTER OF YOU.
YOU KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT BEING HUMAN.
I KNOW THAT FOR THEM,
GUILT CAN BE
A POWERFUL MOTIVATOR.
DON'T LET IT
CLOUD YOUR JUDGMENT.
MAYBE YOU'D BE
A LITTLE MORE CONCERNED
IF VULCAN WAS IN DANGER
AND NOT EARTH.
WE'LL MEET WITH DEGRA.
I'LL SPEAK TO THE XINDI COUNCIL.
BUT DEGRA'S NOT EXPECTING US.
ARCHER'S FOLLOWING THE SAME
COURSE OF ACTION HE DID BEFORE.
HE'S NOT GOING TO BE
AT THE RENDEZVOUS.
BUT THEIR PLAN COULD WORK.
WE CAN'T JUST SIT HERE
AND HOPE HE SUCCEEDS.
BILLIONS OF LIVES ARE AT STAKE.
H-HOW ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO REACH DEGRA?
WE CAN'T SUSTAIN WARP 6.
OUR INJECTORS ARE TOO OLD.
WE'RE GOING TO USE THE INJECTORS
FROM ARCHER'S SHIP.
DO YOU EXPECT HIM
TO SIMPLY GIVE THEM TO US?
NO.
YOU'RE GOING TO STEAL THEM?
THEIR WARP DRIVE
WILL BE DISABLED.
MY FATHER'S
A RESOURCEFUL ENGINEER.
HE'LL BE ABLE TO
FABRICATE NEW INJECTORS.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO BETRAY JONATHAN ARCHER.
I KNOW THIS WON'T BE EASY,
BUT WE'VE HAD TO MAKE
DIFFICULT CHOICES BEFORE.
OUR PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS
LIVED AND DIED ABOARD THIS SHIP
TO ENSURE THAT SOMEDAY WE WOULD
BE ABLE TO STOP THE XINDI.
THIS IS OUR TIME.
IF EARTH IS GOING TO SURVIVE,
WE HAVE TO ACT.
HAVE YOU SPENT ANY TIME
TALKING TO LORIAN?
NOT REALLY.
YOU SHOULD.
HE SEEMS LIKE A GOOD KID.
HE'S HARDLY A KID.
HE'S MORE THAN 100 YEARS OLD.
ONLY IN THE EXPANSE
COULD I HAVE A SON
WHO'S NEARLY THREE TIMES MY AGE.
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT?
YOU AND ME, HUH?
LORIAN SAYS
WE'RE GONNA BE MARRIED
IN A TRADITIONAL
VULCAN CEREMONY.
IT'S GONNA TAKE ME WEEKS
TO LEARN TO PRONOUNCE THE VOWS.
YOU KNOW WHERE WE'RE
GONNA HAVE OUR HONEYMOON?
CARGO BAY THREE.
HE SAYS I'LL FILL IT UP
WITH SAND
THEN WE DUG UP
FROM A PASSING ASTEROID.
I'M EVEN SUPPOSED TO...
[ LAUGHS ]
I'M EVEN SUPPOSED
TO MANUFACTURE A PALM TREE.
IT'S RIDICULOUS TO ASSUME THOSE
EVENTS ARE GOING TO HAPPEN.
HAND ME THE FLUX COUPLER.
AREN'T YOU AT ALL CURIOUS
ABOUT HOW YOU AND I ARE SUPPOSED
TO END UP TOGETHER?
THE FACT THAT
OUR COUNTERPARTS MARRIED
DOESN'T MEAN
WE'LL DO THE SAME.
YOU'RE AFRAID TO ADMIT THAT
UNDER THE RIGHT CIRCUMSTANCES,
YOU COULD HAVE FEELINGS FOR ME.
NO, MAYBE YOU HAVE THEM ALREADY.
I SHOULD'VE KNOWN
THIS WAS A MISTAKE.
WHAT?
EXPLORING HUMAN SEXUALITY
WITH YOU.
YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY UNABLE TO HAVE
A PHYSICAL RELATIONSHIP
WITHOUT DEVELOPING
AN EMOTIONAL ATTACHMENT.
YOU KNOW, ALL THE OTHER WOMEN
ONBOARD MUST HAVE BEEN TAKEN,
'CAUSE I CAN'T IMAGINE
ANY OTHER REASON
WHY I WOULD HAVE MARRIED
SOMEONE AS STUBBORN AS YOU.
I'LL GO HELP ROSTOV
WITH THE PORT MANIFOLD.
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
EVERYTHING UNDER CONTROL.
INJECTORS ARE STILL ONLINE.
GREER, HOW MUCH LONGER?
IT'S TAKING MORE TIME THAN WE
THOUGHT TO REROUTE THE PLASMA.
-Stand by.
-HOLD OFF ON IT FOR NOW.
I WANT THOSE STARBOARD MODULES
RECALIBRATED FIRST.
UGH!
HOLD YOUR FIRE.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Greer to Lorian.
THE FLOW'S BEEN DIVERTED.
GET BACK TO THE SHIP. GO.
WE WON'T BE ABLE TO GO TO WARP
WITHOUT THOSE INJECTORS
ARCHER GAVE ME NO OTHER OPTION.
TAKE SOME ADVICE
FROM YOUR OLD MAN.
YOU DON'T WANT TO DO THIS.
HE'LL ALERT THE OTHERS.
I'M SORRY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
WARP ENGINES JUST WENT OFFLINE.
OUR PLASMA INJECTORS
ARE DISENGAGED.
ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
TRIP, RESPOND.
SEND A SECURITY TEAM.
THEY'VE UNDOCKED.
HAIL THEM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
NO RESPONSE.
THEY'RE PREPARING
TO GO TO WARP.
DISABLE THEIR ENGINES.
THEY'RE TARGETING OUR NACELLES.
TAKE US TO WARP.
I CAN'T. THEY'VE KNOCKED OUT
THE STARBOARD POWER COUPLINGS.
GET US OUT OF HERE,
FULL IMPULSE.
RETURN FIRE.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
HULL PLATING AT 61%.
-THEY'RE MAKING A RUN FOR IT.
-STAY WITH THEM.
THEY HAVE THE SAME COMPLEMENT
OF WEAPONS AS WE DO.
WE WOULD APPEAR
TO BE EVENLY MATCHED.
GET DOWN TO THE TRANSPORTER,
AND STAND BY.
BRING US IN LOW,
UNDERNEATH THEM.
TARGET THEIR
HULL PLATING RELAYS.
-WE'VE LOST HULL PLATING!
-T'POL?
I CAN'T ESTABLISH A LOCK.
We need to get closer.
YOU HEARD HER.
WE LOST POWER ON "C" DECK.
WEAPONS ARE GONE.
2,000 METERS.
T'POL!
SIR, OUR WEAPONS
ARE LOSING POWER.
ARCHER'S USING
THE TRANSPORTER.
THEY'VE TAKEN ONE OF
OUR E.P.S. MANIFOLDS.
NOW LOCK ONTO
THEIR PRIMARY RELAYS.
THEY'RE ON "C" DECK,
JUNCTION 12.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE LOSING MAIN POWER.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
LOOKS LIKE
WE'VE GOT SOME THINGS
THAT BELONG TO EACH OTHER.
WHY DON'T WE CALL A TRUCE
AND RETURN
OUR RESPECTIVE PROPERTY?
SIR.
THEY STILL HAVE ONE TORPEDO
IN THE FORWARD TUBE.
IT'S LOCKED ONTO
OUR STARBOARD ENGINE.
I KNOW YOU'VE GOT YOUR FINGER
ON THE TRIGGER.
IF YOU FIRE THAT TORPEDO,
YOU'RE GOING TO HURT
A LOT OF PEOPLE OVER HERE.
LORIAN, ANSWER ME.
WE CAN'T DO THIS.
THERE'S TOO MUCH AT STAKE.
THESE PEOPLE ARE FAMILY.
I'M NOT GOING TO
LET YOU KILL THEM.
CAPTAIN, IT'S OVER.
STAND DOWN WEAPONS.
TELL ARCHER I WANT TO TALK.
YOU WERE LUCKY.
PHLOX SAYS THE INJURIES
ON BOTH SHIPS WERE MINOR.
YOU ALMOST CRIPPLED US.
MY MISSION WOULD
HAVE BEEN OVER.
YOUR MISSION IS OVER, CAPTAIN.
YOU JUST WON'T ACCEPT IT.
I TOOK THE ONLY
LOGICAL COURSE OF ACTION.
ATTACKING YOUR ANCESTORS
DOESN'T SOUND
VERY LOGICAL TO ME.
YOU WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU CAN'T.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
LIVING WITH THE RESPONSIBILITY.
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
ARE DEAD BECAUSE OF ME.
I'M SURE YOUR CREW DID
EVERYTHING THEY COULD
TO STOP THE PROBE.
I COULD HAVE DESTROYED IT!
YEARS AGO, I SWORE TO MY CAPTAIN
ON HIS DEATHBED
I'D SAVE THOSE 7 MILLION LIVES.
YOU WERE THE MAN
I MADE THAT PROMISE TO.
I DEVOTED MY LIFE
TO THAT MISSION.
WE KNEW THE COORDINATES
OF THE LAUNCH PLATFORM,
THE EXACT MINUTE THE WEAPON
WAS GOING TO BE DEPLOYED.
BUT OUR PLAN DIDN'T WORK.
I HAD ONE LAST CHANCE.
USE ENTERPRISE ITSELF, SET A
COLLISION COURSE WITH THE PROBE.
BUT I HESITATED.
MY EMOTIONS TOOK OVER.
I COULDN'T GIVE AN ORDER
THAT WOULD KILL MY CREW.
BY THE TIME
I REALIZED MY MISTAKE,
IT WAS TOO LATE.
THE PROBE WAS GONE.
I WON'T LET MY EMOTIONS
GET IN THE WAY AGAIN.
I WILL NOT LET EARTH
BE DESTROYED.
I COULD KEEP YOU
LOCKED UP IN HERE.
BUT THAT WOULDN'T DO
EITHER OF US ANY GOOD.
ALL THAT MATTERS
IS WHAT WE'RE GOING
TO DO NEXT.
WHETHER YOU
AGREE WITH IT OR NOT,
I'M TAKING MY SHIP
INTO THAT CORRIDOR.
AND I'LL STAND
A MUCH BETTER CHANCE
OF COMPLETING THIS MISSION,
OUR MISSION,
IF WE WORK TOGETHER.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
AM I DISTURBING YOU?
NOT AT ALL.
PLEASE.
TEA?
CHAMOMILE?
OF COURSE.
WE HAD TROUBLE WITH
YOUR MODIFICATIONS.
WE WERE ONLY ABLE TO REDUCE
OUR PARTICLE WAKE BY 86%.
THE CORRIDOR COULD
DESTABILIZE AGAIN.
IF YOU PLACE
AN ISOMAGNETIC COLLECTOR HERE,
IT SHOULD ABSORB
ANY RESIDUAL PARTICLES.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH THAT TYPE OF DEVICE.
IT'S SOMETHING WE PICKED UP
FROM THE IKAARANS.
I SHOULD BE ABLE TO
FIND THE SCHEMATICS.
ARE YOU FEELING BETTER?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOUR TRELLIUM ADDICTION.
HAVE THE SYMPTOMS DIMINISHED?
TO A DEGREE.
BUT I HAVEN'T FULLY RECOVERED.
YOU'LL NEVER FULLY RECOVER.
THE EMOTIONS YOU'VE ACCESSED
WILL BE WITH YOU
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
AH. HERE WE ARE.
DON'T FORGET YOUR TEA.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO LEARN
TO EMBRACE THEM,
LIVE WITH THEM AS I HAVE.
THERE'S SOMEONE ON YOUR SHIP
WHO CAN HELP.
PHLOX HAS ALREADY GIVEN ME
A NEURAL SUPPRESSANT.
I DON'T MEAN PHLOX.
TRIP CAN BE AN OUTLET
FOR THESE FEELINGS
IF YOU'LL TRUST HIM.
THE EMOTIONS HE STIRRED IN ME
WERE POWERFUL...AND FRIGHTENING.
I TRIED TO PUSH HIM AWAY.
IF ENTERPRISE HADN'T BEEN
STRANDED IN THE PAST,
IT'S POSSIBLE I NEVER
WOULD HAVE MARRIED TRIP.
BUT I CAN'T IMAGINE
WHAT MY LIFE
WOULD HAVE BEEN LIKE
WITHOUT HIM.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST I DO?
THERE'S A HUMAN EXPRESSION --
FOLLOW YOUR HEART.
WHAT IF MY HEART DOESN'T KNOW
WHAT IT WANTS?
IT WILL...
IN TIME.
IT WILL.
WEAPONS ARE STANDING BY.
TAKE US IN.
ARE THE SIGNATURES
BEING REFLECTED?
I'M READING MULTIPLE IMAGES.
HOW LONG UNTIL
WE REACH THE CORRIDOR?
SIX MINUTES.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THEY'VE DETECTED US.
THREE SHIPS ARE
ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
RETURN FIRE!
THE NEBULA'S INTERFERING
WITH OUR TARGETING SCANNERS.
WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT
UNTIL THEY GET CLOSER.
THEY DON'T SEEM TO BE HAVING
THE SAME PROBLEM.
-AFT PLATING'S AT 42%.
-MALCOLM!
JUST A FEW MORE SECONDS, SIR.
WE HAVE A LOCK.
ARCHER TO LORIAN.
NOW!
THE LEAD SHIP'S DISABLED.
THE OTHER TWO ARE FALLING BACK.
WELL DONE, CAPTAIN.
THEY MUST HAVE
BEEN SURPRISED
WHEN YOUR REFLECTION TURNED
AND ATTACKED THEM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
SIR, WE'RE LOSING SPEED.
-Tucker to the bridge!
-GO AHEAD.
THAT LAST TORPEDO TOOK OUT
THE PRIMARY DRIVE COIL!
I've got to shut down
the port engine!
UNDERSTOOD.
LORIAN.
IT LOOKS LIKE WE'RE NOT GONNA BE
ABLE TO KEEP UP WITH YOU.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THE ALIENS ARE REGROUPING --
FOUR SHIPS.
BRING US 100 METERS
OFF ARCHER'S BOW.
POWER THE TRACTOR EMITTERS.
CAPTAIN, TELL YOUR CREW
TO BRACE THEMSELVES.
WE'RE INCREASING SPEED.
THEY'VE ENGAGED
A TRACTOR BEAM.
THANKS FOR THE LIFT.
WE'LL SEE YOU ON
THE OTHER SIDE.
SIR, THE KOVAALANS WILL
BE IN WEAPONS RANGE
IN LESS THAN 20 SECONDS.
THE ALIENS ARE CLOSING.
12,000 METERS. 10,000.
TARGET THEIR WEAPONS!
HULL PLATING'S HOLDING.
WHAT ABOUT ARCHER?
THEIR AFT PLATING'S ALMOST GONE.
SEE IF WE CAN GET
THE ALIENS' ATTENTION.
TORPEDOES, FULL SPREAD.
WE'VE LOST AFT PLATING.
45 SECONDS TO THE CORRIDOR.
WEAPONS ARE DOWN.
THEY'RE TARGETING
ARCHER'S REACTOR.
DISENGAGE THE TRACTOR BEAM.
NEW COURSE -- 180 MARK ZERO.
We'll keep them
off your back.
Your momentum will carry you
into the corridor.
WE'LL FOLLOW AS SOON AS WE CAN.
TELL MY PARENTS
THAT I'LL SEE THEM SOON.
12 SECONDS TO THE CORRIDOR.
DIRECT HIT. THE PYLONS
ARE STARTING TO BUCKLE.
RESERVE POWER TO HULL PLATING.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
HULL INTEGRITY'S FAILING.
UGH! FORWARD LAUNCHERS ARE GONE!
DIVERT EVERYTHING
TO THE PHASE CANNONS!
CONTINUE FIRING!
NO SIGN OF PURSUIT.
WHERE ARE WE?
WE'VE TRAVELED 11.6 LIGHT-YEARS.
ARE WE STILL IN
THE RIGHT CENTURY?
THE STARS ARE WHERE
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE.
WHAT ABOUT LORIAN?
NO SIGN OF HIM YET, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
IT'S BEEN FIVE HOURS,
AND THE OTHER ENTERPRISE
STILL HASN'T ARRIVED.
REPAIRS TO OUR IMPULSE DRIVE
ARE UNDERWAY.
ONE SHIP AGAINST FOUR.
IT'S UNLIKELY THEY SURVIVED.
LORIAN HAS YEARS
OF COMMAND EXPERIENCE.
SOMETHING TELLS ME WE SHOULDN'T
WRITE HIM OFF YET.
I SUPPOSE THERE'S
ANOTHER POSSIBILITY.
SINCE WE WEREN'T
THROWN INTO THE PAST,
MAYBE HISTORY
SOMEHOW CORRECTED ITSELF.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING THAT THE
OTHER ENTERPRISE NEVER EXISTED?
IF YOU'RE RIGHT...
THEN WHY WOULD WE REMEMBER THEM?
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
Could you come out here, sir?
A SHIP'S DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
IT'S DEGRA.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
HE'S HAILING US.
PUT HIM UP.
CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE EARLY.
[ SIGHS ]