PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
WE'RE 400 YEARS IN THE FUTURE.
YOU KNOW ABOUT
THE ALIEN WE FOUND?
THE TEST SUBJECT?
HE BELONGS TO THE SAME RACE
THAT BUILT THE SPHERES.
THEY'RE ALTERING THIS SPACE
TO MAKE IT HABITABLE
FOR THEIR SPECIES.
YOU HAVE TO
MAKE THE XINDI UNDERSTAND
THAT HUMANITY ISN'T THE ENEMY.
THE WEAPON WON'T BE LAUNCHED
FOR SEVERAL DAYS.
SHOW US YOUR PROOF.
YOU'RE SAYING THE EXPANSE WILL
NO LONGER BE COMPATIBLE FOR US.
FOR ANY OF US.
WE'RE DESTINED TO FORM
AN ALLIANCE TO STOP THEM.
YOU NEED TO
SPEAK TO THE COUNCIL.
WITH THE EVIDENCE
YOU'VE SHOWN ME,
THEY'LL HAVE NO CHOICE
BUT TO TAKE US SERIOUSLY.
IF IT WEREN'T FOR MY ASSISTANCE,
YOUR SPECIES WOULD BE
FACING DESTRUCTION.
IS IT TRUE YOUR SPECIES
BUILT THE SPHERES?
WHERE IS DEGRA?
WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS
DO YOU HAVE?
YOU EXPECT ME TO ATTACK
A REPTILIAN WARSHIP?
THE REPTILIAN VESSEL'S
BEEN DESTROYED.
THEY WOULD HAVE CONTACTED
THE COUNCIL
AND EXPOSED OUR ALLIANCE.
HE'LL BE KILLED THE MOMENT
HE STEPS INTO THE COUNCIL
CHAMBER.
IF ARCHER IS TELLING THE TRUTH,
THEN ALL THE COUNCIL'S EFFORTS
WILL BE FOR NOTHING.
WE'VE BEEN SUCCESSFUL.
THE XINDI WEAPON IS
DAYS AWAY FROM COMPLETION.
THE TIMELINES DON'T SUPPORT
THAT ASSESSMENT.
WHAT HAVE YOU SEEN?
THE NUMBER OF LINES
WITH FAVORABLE OUTCOMES
HAS DIMINISHED.
THERE IS NOW AN INCREASED CHANCE
THAT THE EARTH SHIP
WILL PREVENT THE WEAPON
FROM BEING LAUNCHED.
NOT NECESSARILY.
TIMELINES ARE SENSITIVE.
THEY'RE PRONE TO
TEMPORARY FLUCTUATIONS.
THIS IS NO FLUCTUATION.
THIS IS A TRAJECTORY AWAY
FROM OUR DESIRED OUTCOME.
SEE THAT YOU TAKE DEFINITIVE
ACTIONS
TO CORRECT THIS.
THE WEAPON MUST BE LAUNCHED.
EARTH MUST BE DESTROYED.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
I'M NOT DETECTING ANY TRELLIUM
IN YOUR SYSTEM.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
THE EMOTIONS ARE STILL
DIFFICULT TO CONTROL.
MEDITATION ISN'T HELPING?
SOMEWHAT, BUT I'M STILL
EXPERIENCING FREQUENT --
YOU OKAY?
JUST A MILD HEADACHE.
I THOUGHT VULCANS
DIDN'T GET HEADACHES.
I'M NEEDED
IN THE COMMAND CENTER.
YOU NOTICE ANYTHING STRANGE
ABOUT THE WAY SHE'S BEEN ACTING?
THERE ISN'T ANYONE ON THE SHIP
WHO HASN'T BEEN AFFECTED
BY RECENT EVENTS.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
I THINK I PULLED A MUSCLE.
PAIN'S PRETTY BAD.
HAVE A SEAT.
WE'VE BEEN RUNNING DOUBLE SHIFTS
IN ENGINEERING.
CAPTAIN'S IN A HELL OF A RUSH
TO GET TO THIS DAMN COUNCIL.
HE BELIEVES HE CAN GET THE XINDI
TO RECONSIDER
THEIR ATTACK ON EARTH.
WE OWE HIM A LITTLE FAITH.
OH, I HAVE FAITH IN THE CAPTAIN,
BUT NOT IN THE PEOPLE
HE'S TRYING TO CONVINCE.
DEGRA SEEMS TO BE
A REASONABLE MAN.
REASONABLE?
I DON'T THINK MANY PEOPLE
BACK IN MY HOMETOWN
WOULD GO ALONG WITH THAT.
THANKS, DOC.
THE SPHERES ARE CONTROLLED
BY A NETWORK
OF ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE.
THIS SECTION HOUSES
THE REDUNDANT MEMORY CORE.
IT SHOULD CONTAIN A SIGNIFICANT
AMOUNT OF INFORMATION.
WE'RE HOPING THAT'LL INCLUDE
DATA ON THE SPHERE BUILDERS.
THAT COULD HELP US
WITH THE COUNCIL.
OUR PRESENT COURSE WILL TAKE US
CLOSE TO ANOTHER SPHERE.
I'M SENDING A CREW
IN A SHUTTLEPOD.
THEY'LL JOIN UP WITH US LATER.
HOW DO YOU PLAN
TO GET INSIDE IT?
WE'RE PRETTY SURE
WE'VE FOUND A WAY IN.
YOU'VE MENTIONED
THE XINDI HAVE BEEN
STUDYING THE SPHERES
FOR DECADES.
WE'RE INTERESTED
IN ANY INFORMATION
YOU HAVE ON THE CONSTRUCTION
OF THEIR OUTER SHELLS.
I'LL SEND OVER WHATEVER'S
IN MY DATABASE.
SIR.
I'VE BEEN REVIEWING
SERVICE TRANSCRIPTS.
YOU'VE GOT OVER 1,000 HOURS
IN AN E.V. SUIT.
I DID SIX MONTHS
ON THE JANUS LOOP.
YOU INTERESTED IN RUNNING
THIS MISSION WITH US?
I'M ALWAYS READY
TO STRETCH MY LEGS, SIR.
GET PREPPED.
THE JANUS, THAT INCLUDES
E.V. COMBAT TRAINING?
YES, SIR.
ARE WE EXPECTING A FIREFIGHT?
DON'T KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT.
WHEN IT'S FINISHED COMPILING,
SEND IT TO ENTERPRISE.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
DISMISSED.
DISMISSED!
NOT EVERYONE HAS FORGOTTEN
WHAT WE'VE DONE FOR YOUR PEOPLE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOU'VE TURNED AWAY FROM US.
COME BACK.
I CAN'T.
I HEAR IT IN YOUR VOICE.
YOU'VE BETRAYED
EVERYTHING YOU BELIEVE IN,
AND NOW YOU'RE IN TURMOIL.
I DON'T REGRET WHAT I'M DOING.
AT ONE TIME OR ANOTHER,
YOU MUST HAVE ASKED YOURSELF
WHY WE'VE PROTECTED THE XINDI
FOR SO LONG.
MANY OF US HAVE WONDERED THAT.
IT'S BECAUSE WE CAN SEE A FUTURE
WHERE THE XINDI
ARE NO LONGER FRAGMENTED,
NO LONGER
STRUGGLING FOR EXISTENCE.
YOU ARE DESTINED TO BECOME
A GREAT CIVILIZATION.
AND NOW IT'S ALL IN JEOPARDY...
BECAUSE OF YOU.
NO.
YOU CREATED A DEVICE THAT WILL
PREVENT A DEVASTATING ATTACK.
YOUR NAME WAS TO BE SPOKEN
WITH REVERENCE
FOR GENERATIONS TO COME.
AND INSTEAD, YOU'VE CHOSEN
THE ROLE OF BETRAYER.
HOW I'M REMEMBERED
ISN'T FOR YOU TO DECIDE.
WHAT HAVE WE DONE
TO LOSE YOUR FAITH?
YOU NEVER DESERVED MY FAITH.
THE SPHERE BUILDERS
HAVE LIED TO THE XINDI.
THEY'VE MANIPULATED US
FOR DECADES.
I SEE THAT.
PERHAPS THE ARBOREALS WILL,
BUT THE OTHERS...
WE HAVE THE EVIDENCE
TO BACK IT UP.
THE EVIDENCE MAY NOT BE ENOUGH.
THE SPHERE BUILDERS SAVED
THE XINDI FROM EXTINCTION.
WHEN OUR HOMEWORLD
WAS DESTROYED,
THEY BEGAN APPEARING
TO THE SURVIVORS.
THEY'D GUIDE THEM
TO HABITABLE PLANETS,
SHOW THEM THE LOCATION
OF VALUABLE RESOURCES.
THEY'RE PRACTICALLY WORSHIPED.
WE CALL THEM "THE GUARDIANS."
IT'S NO WONDER YOU HAD
A HARD TIME ACCEPTING THIS.
I WAS BROUGHT UP TO REVERE THEM.
I TAUGHT MY OWN CHILDREN
TO GIVE THANKS TO THEM
AT THE END OF EACH DAY.
THAT IS WHAT WE'RE FACING.
I'VE STOOD BEFORE
A KLINGON TRIBUNAL.
I CAN HANDLE A TOUGH ROOM.
KLINGONS WEREN'T DETERMINED
TO DESTROY YOUR WORLD.
BUT THE EVIDENCE IS STRONG.
PERHAPS IT WILL BE ENOUGH.
WE'LL FACE THE COUNCIL TOGETHER.
I MAY TAKE MY SEAT
AT THE COUNCIL TABLE,
BUT I'LL BE AT YOUR SIDE
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
We've picked up
several Xindi vessels.
They're closing on our position.
HUMANOIDS, ARBOREALS,
AND AQUATICS.
THEY'RE WITH US.
WHEN WE REACH
THE COUNCIL'S LOCATION,
WE'LL NEED THEIR PROTECTION.
CERTAIN MEMBERS HAVE
MORE INFLUENCE THAN OTHERS.
ANYTHING YOU CAN
TELL ME ABOUT THEM?
I NEED TO KNOW
WHAT I'M UP AGAINST.
YOU KNOW JANNAR, THE ARBOREAL.
HE'S FAIR-MINDED, A SCIENTIST.
HE'LL LISTEN TO THE FACTS.
I COUNT HIM AS A FRIEND.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE OTHER MEMBERS
ARE SOMEWHAT MORE COMPLICATED.
THE AQUATICS, FOR INSTANCE.
KIAPHET AMMAN'SOR IS A MEMBER
OF THE IBIX DYNASTY,
A VERY WEALTHY,
VERY POWERFUL FAMILY.
HER OPINIONS CARRY CONSIDERABLE
WEIGHT WHEN SHE ARRIVES AT THEM.
THERE'S A SAYING, "IT'S EASIER
TO COUNT THE STARS IN THE SKY
THAN IT IS FOR AN AQUATIC
TO REACH A DECISION."
AS FOR THE INSECTOIDS,
WELL, THEIR NAMES GROW LONGER
THE OLDER THEY GET,
SO THEY BECOME A LITTLE
DIFFICULT TO PRONOUNCE.
IN MANY WAYS, INSECTOIDS ARE
THE OPPOSITE OF THE AQUATICS.
THEY'RE QUICK TO TAKE SIDES.
WE'VE RUN INTO THEM.
WHICH BRINGS US TO THE
REPTILIANS AND COMMANDER DOLIM.
THERE'S A STORY ABOUT HIM.
I DON'T KNOW THAT IT'S TRUE.
I'D LIKE TO BELIEVE IT ISN'T.
HIS DAUGHTER
GAVE BIRTH TO A SON.
HE HAD A DEFORMITY IN HIS
RIGHT ARM, NOT LIFE-THREATENING,
BUT ENOUGH TO PRECLUDE
HIS EVER JOINING THE MILITARY.
COMMANDER DOLIM
HAD HIS OWN GRANDSON POISONED.
FROM WHAT I'VE SEEN,
THAT'S NOT HARD TO BELIEVE.
AS I SAID,
IT MAY BE JUST A STORY,
BUT AS A FATHER, IT'S ALWAYS
IN THE BACK OF MY MIND
WHENEVER I HAVE
DEALINGS WITH HIM.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
ENTER.
WHAT IS IT?
WE'VE LOCATED DEBRIS.
IT'S FROM THE SHIP WE SENT
TO FIND DEGRA.
WHERE?
SEVEN LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE,
WITHIN THE CLOAKING BARRIER
OF A SPHERE.
I WANT TO KNOW
HOW IT WAS DESTROYED.
BEGIN AN ANALYSIS.
IT'S UNDER WAY.
PRELIMINARY FINDINGS
SUGGEST THEY WERE ATTACKED.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-YES.
Commander, there are
six vessels approaching.
One is the Earth ship.
CONTACT THE LEAD SHIP.
THIS IS DEGRA.
DEGRA, I WAS JUST
THINKING OF YOU.
HOW MANY PRISONERS
HAVE YOU TAKEN?
WE'RE ESCORTING ENTERPRISE
TO THE COUNCIL.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
POWER DOWN YOUR WEAPONS
AND WITHDRAW.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I WOULD LET YOU BRING
AN ENEMY SHIP
INTO A SECURITY ZONE?
POWER DOWN YOUR WEAPONS NOW.
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU.
THEY'VE LAUNCHED A TORPEDO.
WHAT?
[ RUMBLING ]
300 METERS OFF THE PORT BOW.
YOU WOULD FIRE
ON A XINDI VESSEL?
WE'RE PREPARED TO DESTROY
YOUR VESSEL, IF NECESSARY.
THEY'RE LOCKING WEAPONS.
PREPARE TO RETURN FIRE!
YOU'RE OUTNUMBERED
AND OUTGUNNED.
THERE'S NO NEED FOR THIS.
I ASSURE YOU, THE EARTH SHIP
POSES NO DANGER.
I'LL SEE YOU
IN THE COUNCIL CHAMBER.
I LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
5 SECONDS.
3, 2...
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
R.C.S. INVERTER.
SHUT IT DOWN.
DAMAGE?
NOTHING WE NEED
TO WORRY ABOUT, SIR.
ADJUST HEADING 026 MARK 3.
I'D BREATHE A WHOLE LOT EASIER
IF YOU HAD A COUPLE OF MACOS
WATCHING YOUR BACK.
DON'T WORRY.
KEEP MY CHAIR WARM.
GOOD LUCK.
HOW'S YOUR INSECTOID THESE DAYS?
IT DEPENDS ON WHICH DIALECT.
THERE ARE 67.
IS THAT ALL?
AQUATICS RESPECT BOLDNESS
AND CONFIDENCE.
THEY VIEW HUSHED TONES
WITH SUSPICION.
I'LL MAKE SURE I PROJECT.
NOT TOO LOUDLY.
THE INSECTOIDS INTERPRET RAISED
VOICES AS A SIGN OF HOSTILITY.
WHEN AQUATICS USE THE PAST
TENSE,
THEY SWITCH TO SONAR.
WE SHOULD SEE IT IN A MOMENT.
WE'RE STILL 2 KILOMETERS UP.
THE ONLY WAY IN IS FROM THE AIR.
THESE CLOUD LAYERS ARE PRESENT
THROUGHOUT THE YEAR.
IT'S PERFECTLY CONCEALED.
AVIANS.
OH, IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THE SIXTH XINDI RACE.
THIS WAS BUILT CENTURIES
BEFORE THEY BECAME EXTINCT.
ACCORDING TO OUR ARCHAEOLOGISTS,
IT'S OVER 4,000 YEARS OLD.
KIND OF FEELS LIKE BEING CALLED
TO THE PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE.
I WAS NEVER CALLED
I WAS ONCE.
MOVE ASIDE.
WHAT FOR?
WHEN WE'RE DONE HERE.
[ CHITTERING ]
[ CLICKING ]
YOU'VE BROUGHT HUMANS
INTO THIS CHAMBER, DEGRA.
EXPLAIN YOURSELF IF YOU
EXPECT THEM TO LEAVE HERE ALIVE.
I'M FULLY PREPARED
TO EXPLAIN MY ACTIONS.
THERE'S NO CAUSE FOR THREATS.
AGREED.
WE'VE REVIEWED
THE DATA YOU'VE SENT.
WE ARE PREPARED TO LISTEN
TO WHAT YOU HAVE TO SAY.
YOU KILLED 7 MILLION
OF MY PEOPLE.
I WANT TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
I DON'T MUCH LIKE STANDING HERE.
WE DID WHAT WE FELT
WAS NECESSARY.
I KNOW.
YOU'VE BEEN TOLD THAT
AT SOME TIME IN THE FUTURE
MY WORLD
IS GOING TO DESTROY YOURS.
THAT'S A LIE.
[ CHITTERS ]
HE SAID, "THE GUARDIANS
HAVE NEVER LIED TO US."
THE GUARDIANS BUILT THE SPHERES.
THEY'RE RECONFIGURING
THE EXPANSE,
PREPARING IT FOR COLONIZATION.
YOU REEK OF DESPERATION.
YOU WOULD SAY ANYTHING
TO SAVE YOUR WORLD,
AS EVIDENCED
BY THIS MANUFACTURED DATA.
IT'S THE TRUTH!
THE DATA IS ACCURATE.
ANYONE WITH AN OBJECTIVE EYE
WILL COME
TO THE SAME CONCLUSION.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT THE TRUTH IS.
YOUR SYMPATHY FOR THESE HUMANS
HAS CORRUPTED YOUR JUDGMENT.
MY JUDGMENT IS PERFECTLY SOUND.
WERE YOU USING SOUND JUDGMENT
WHEN YOU ATTACKED MY SHIP?
YOU WERE TRYING TO PREVENT US
FROM REACHING THIS COUNCIL!
I WAS PROTECTING THIS COUNCIL!
[ SCREECHING ]
[ BEEPING ]
"THIS IS NOT RELEVANT.
WE'RE HERE TO DISCUSS
THE HUMAN'S CLAIMS."
AGREED. WE NEED TO RETURN
TO THE SUBJECT AT HAND.
[ GRUNTS ]
I AM TRYING TO SAVE MY WORLD.
BUT IT'S NOT JUST EARTH
THAT'S IN DANGER.
IF YOU WIPE OUT MANKIND,
YOU'LL BE DESTROYING YOURSELF.
I REFUSE TO LISTEN
TO ANY MORE OF THIS!
EARTH IS GOING TO LEAD A BATTLE
THAT DEFEATS
THE SPHERE BUILDERS.
THEY KNOW THIS.
THAT'S WHY THEY MANIPULATED YOU
INTO ATTACKING US.
ENOUGH!
I DEMAND THE IMMEDIATE SEIZURE
OF THE EARTH SHIP.
ANY VESSEL THAT ATTACKS
ENTERPRISE WILL BE FIRED UPON!
YOU WILL NOT DEFY THIS COUNCIL!
WE HAVEN'T ARRIVED
AT A DECISION YET!
AND WE NEVER WILL AS LONG AS
WE LISTEN TO THIS HUMAN'S LIES!
IF THIS COUNCIL
WILL NOT DEFEND ITS PEOPLE,
THEN IT HAS NO REASON TO EXIST.
WAIT.
[ GROANS ]
[ CHITTERS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ INSECTOID CHITTERING ]
[ BEEPS ]
YOU DON'T WANT TO KNOW.
HOLD THIS POSITION.
THE EXHAUST VENT.
WHERE?
SET A COURSE, 031 MARK 4.
I DON'T SEE AN EXHAUST VENT.
YOU SURE ABOUT THIS?
HALF THRUSTERS.
[ BEEPING ]
T'POL!
HOLD YOUR COURSE.
-I'M TELLING YOU!
-HOLD YOUR COURSE!
[ BEEPING ]
SOME KIND OF HOLOGRAM?
EXACTLY.
YOU COULD HAVE WARNED US
AHEAD OF TIME.
PROCEED ALONG THIS CONDUIT.
AYE.
60 DEGREES STARBOARD.
80 DEGREES Z-AXIS.
WE SHOULD PREPARE FOR E.V.A.
LET'S BREAK OUT THE SUITS.
WE'VE HAD
DIFFICULT SESSIONS BEFORE
IN THE DAYS FOLLOWING
THE FOUNDING OF THIS COUNCIL.
THIS IS DIFFERENT.
THE COUNCIL IS ON THE VERGE
OF TEARING ITSELF APART.
YOU UNDERESTIMATE US.
WE WERE ALL IN THE SAME ROOM.
YOU SAW WHAT HAPPENED.
WE KNEW IT WASN'T
GOING TO BE EASY.
WE ARE NEVER GOING TO
CONVINCE THE REPTILIANS
OR THE INSECTOIDS!
THEN WE'LL FOCUS
ON THE AQUATICS.
THE AQUATICS WEIGH EVERY
ARGUMENT IN EXCRUCIATING DETAIL.
FOR A LONG TIME, THEY WERE
AGAINST BUILDING THE WEAPON.
WHAT CHANGED THEIR MINDS?
THE GUARDIANS
ADDRESSED THE COUNCIL.
THEY PRESENTED WHAT THEY CLAIMED
WAS A VISUAL RECORD
TAKEN FROM THE FUTURE.
IT SHOWED MANKIND
DESTROYING OUR NEW HOMEWORLD.
THAT CONVINCED THE AQUATICS.
IT WAS POWERFUL EVIDENCE.
THE AVIANS,
ONCE THEY DARKENED THE SKIES
OF XINDUS WITH THEIR NUMBERS.
WE FORMED THE COUNCIL
TO PREVENT OTHER XINDIS
FROM SHARING THEIR FATE.
YOUR COUNCIL JUST MIGHT HAVE
THE OPPOSITE EFFECT.
PERHAPS NOT.
THERE MIGHT BE A WAY
TO CONVINCE THEM.
I'LL REQUIRE THE SERVICES
OF YOUR SHIP'S DOCTOR.
THE COUNCIL IS PREPARING
TO BETRAY ITS OWN PEOPLE.
ARCHER HAS ACHIEVED NOTHING.
HE HAS SUCCEEDED
IN RAISING DOUBTS ABOUT US.
THE ARBOREALS, HUMANOIDS,
AND AQUATICS
ARE CONSIDERING
WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
HE SHOULD NEVER HAVE BEEN
ALLOWED BEFORE THE COUNCIL.
I COULDN'T PREVENT IT.
AND NOW THEY MAY DECIDE
AGAINST LAUNCHING THE WEAPON.
THE WEAPON WILL BE DEPLOYED.
FOR THAT TO HAPPEN, THREE OF
THE XINDI SPECIES MUST AGREE.
IF WE COULD PROVE TO THEM
THAT YOUR PEOPLE
DIDN'T BUILD THE SPHERES --
PROVE TO THEM OR YOU?
MY LIEUTENANT
SIMPLY WANTS TO KNOW
IF THERE'S A WAY
TO PERSUADE THE COUNCIL.
PERSUASION IS NO LONGER
A VIABLE OPTION.
YOU MUST ACT WITH THE
INSECTOIDS, SECURE THE WEAPON.
THE WEAPON'S WELL-GUARDED.
THE CASUALTIES ON BOTH SIDES
WOULD BE HEAVY.
WE'D BE RISKING CIVIL WAR.
A TEMPORARY SCHISM
CANNOT BE AVOIDED,
BUT EVENTUALLY,
REPTILIANS WILL PRESIDE
OVER A STRONGER,
UNIFIED XINDI EMPIRE.
WE WILL GUARANTEE
REPTILIAN DOMINANCE.
IF HUMANKIND IS ERADICATED.
UNDERSTOOD.
IF YOU EVER QUESTION
THE GUARDIANS AGAIN,
YOUR SKIN WILL ADORN
THE BOW OF THIS SHIP.
YES, THIS WILL BE VERY HELPFUL.
I'LL HAVE IT SENT OVER
IMMEDIATELY.
I'VE, UH, NEVER HEARD
OF THIS PROCEDURE.
IT WAS DEVELOPED
BY THE AQUATICS.
THEY HAVE AN INNATE DISTRUST
OF THE SPOKEN WORD.
THEY RESPOND MORE STRONGLY
TO VISUAL STIMULI.
YOU NEED ME FOR SOMETHING?
THE TRANSPORT POD
THAT CARRIED THIS ALIEN?
IT'S IN THE CARGO BAY.
THERE ARE SOME MODIFICATIONS
THAT NEED TO BE MADE TO IT.
THE CAPTAIN WOULD LIKE YOU
TO ASSIST ME WITH THE WORK.
LUCKY ME.
YOUR CAPTAIN THINKS
THERE'S NO ONE BETTER
TO MAKE THESE MODIFICATIONS.
I AGREE.
DO ME A FAVOR -- DON'T TRY
TO GET ON MY GOOD SIDE.
LOOK, I UNDERSTAND YOU AND I
WILL ALWAYS BE ENEMIES.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
I CAN'T CHANGE
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR SISTER
OR ANY OF THE 7 MILLION.
BUT I'M RISKING MY LIFE.
I'M RISKING THE LIVES
OF MY FAMILY.
I'VE KILLED MEMBERS
OF MY OWN SPECIES,
ALL BECAUSE I'M TRYING
TO SAVE BOTH OUR WORLDS.
THIS WAY.
[ BEEPING ]
PICKING UP A VERY POWERFUL
ENERGY SIGNATURE.
WE'RE APPROACHING
THE MEMORY CORE.
It's 15 meters ahead.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY GIFT-WRAPPED.
I'M DETECTING
SOME KIND OF MOVEMENT.
Can you pinpoint it?
THERE'S TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE IT IS.
But it's close.
I SUGGEST WE WORK FAST.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
WE'VE COMPLETED THE WORK.
MR. TUCKER WAS...
EXTREMELY COOPERATIVE.
I KNOW IT ISN'T EASY FOR HIM,
WORKING WITH ME.
DEGRA.
WHEN I WAS ON
THE FUTURE ENTERPRISE,
400 YEARS FROM NOW...
THERE WERE XINDI ABOARD.
HUMANS AND XINDI
WERE SERVING TOGETHER
IN THE FEDERATION.
THAT'S A FUTURE
WORTH FIGHTING FOR.
PASSING NOTES.
SIR?
I GOT SENT
TO THE PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE
FOR PASSING A NOTE IN CLASS.
IT WAS TO KATIE BENTLEY.
I WAS INVITING HER TO A PARTY
A FRIEND OF MINE WAS THROWING.
WHAT'D SHE SAY?
FUNNY THING.
SHE'D ALREADY TURNED ME DOWN,
BUT AFTER I GOT IN TROUBLE...
SOME WOMEN CAN'T RESIST
THE BAD BOYS.
AFTER MUCH DELIBERATION,
WE'VE AGREED TO LISTEN
TO THIS NEW EVIDENCE
YOU WISH TO PRESENT.
PROCEED.
THE SPHERE BUILDERS,
THE BEINGS YOU CALL
THE GUARDIANS...
...ARE THE SAME SPECIES.
HAVE YOU MANUFACTURED MORE DATA
TO SUPPORT THIS CLAIM?
A FEW WEEKS AGO,
WE CAME ACROSS AN ALIEN.
HE WAS ADRIFT IN WHAT WE BELIEVE
WAS A TRANS-DIMENSIONAL
DISTURBANCE.
THE ALIEN WAS INSIDE A POD
WHICH WAS CONSTRUCTED OF
THE SAME COMBINATION OF ALLOYS
THAT MAKE UP THE OUTER SHELL
OF THE SPHERES.
HE WAS A SPHERE BUILDER.
[ SCREECHES ]
WE'VE ALREADY PRESENTED
THIS INFORMATION.
NOT ALL OF IT.
ENERGIZE.
YOUR DATA STATES
THAT THIS ALIEN DISINTEGRATED
WHEN IT CAME INTO CONTACT
WITH OUR UNIVERSE.
HE DID.
WHAT YOU'RE SEEING
IS A BIOMETRIC HOLOGRAM.
IT'S THE SAME TECHNOLOGY
USED TO TRAIN OUR PHYSICIANS.
IT WAS CONSTRUCTED
FROM MEDICAL DATA
COLLECTED BY ENTERPRISE'S
MEDICAL OFFICER.
[ CHITTERING ]
"HOW DO WE KNOW THE DATA
USED TO CREATE THIS PHANTOM
WASN'T FALSIFIED?"
HUMANS DON'T HAVE THE TECHNOLOGY
TO PRODUCE A FABRICATION
OF THIS DETAIL.
TELL ME,
IS THIS ONE OF THE GUARDIANS?
THE PHYSICAL RESEMBLANCE
IS HARD TO DENY.
[ SCREECHING ]
"IT IS A GUARDIAN."
[ CHITTERING ]
"WE ARE NOT DECEIVED
BY THIS ILLUSION.
"RESTORE THE DIGNITY
OF OUR COUNCIL.
EXPEL THE HUMANS
FROM THIS CHAMBER."
WE ARE OPEN TO HEARING MORE.
SO ARE WE.
[ SCREECHING ]
"WE AGREE."
PLEASE, CONTINUE.
[ BEEPING ]
REED TO SHUTTLEPOD ONE.
ANYTHING?
No, sir.
WHATEVER IT WAS,
IT'S STOPPED MOVING.
GOT SOMETHING.
IT'S HEADING IN YOUR DIRECTION,
-Moving fast.
-I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
WHERE IS IT?
GIVE ME A POSITION!
IT'S COMING DOWN FROM
THE UPPER LEFT QUADRANT.
ARE YOU SURE?
Damn sure.
IT'S 70 METERS AWAY.
50 METERS.
30.
15!
I SEE IT.
[ SCREAMS ]
HAWKINS!
GO! GO!
FIVE MORE HEADED THIS WAY!
MOVE!
I STILL CAN'T PIN DOWN
THE PROBLEM WITH THE CONVERTER.
I THINK IT'S
AN ENERGY DRAIN SOMEWHERE.
WE'RE FAR FROM 100%.
THERE'S BEEN A DEVELOPMENT.
DISMISSED.
WE HAVE THE THREE VOTES WE NEED.
THE REPTILIANS HAVE AGREED
TO POSTPONE THE LAUNCH
OF THE WEAPON.
THEY'LL NEED MORE CONVINCING
BEFORE THEY SOLIDIFY
THEIR POSITION,
BUT THIS IS A SIGNIFICANT STEP.
THAT FUTURE YOU SPOKE OF...
PERHAPS THIS IS WHERE IT BEGINS.
QUESTION.
THOSE PORTABLE POWER CELLS
YOU LEFT US.
WE'RE HAVING A LITTLE TROUBLE
GETTING THEM IN SYNC.
THINK YOU CAN STICK AROUND FOR
A FEW MINUTES, GIVE ME A HAND?
OF COURSE.
WE'LL BE IN MY READY ROOM.
LISTEN.
ABOUT ALL THOSE THINGS
I'VE BEEN SAYING...
I JUST WANT TO TELL YOU...
...I KNOW YOU WENT OUT
ON A LIMB.
IF I'D SUFFERED YOUR LOSS,
I'D FEEL THE SAME WAY.
SHALL WE GET TO WORK?
IT'S OVER HERE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I WASN'T EXPECTING YOU.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
WE NEED TO DISCUSS.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
I'VE NEVER LIKED THIS PLACE.
I'VE ALWAYS FOUND IT
TO BE PEACEFUL.
IT'S TOO EXPOSED.
REPTILIANS PREFER
TO BE NEAR THE GROUND.
AND THEN THERE'S THE STENCH.
STENCH?
OF FAILURE.
OF A RACE THAT FAILED
TO SURVIVE.
I WAS SURPRISED BY YOUR DECISION
TO POSTPONE THE LAUNCH.
IT SEEMED LIKE
THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
I HOPE THE OTHER MEMBERS WILL
COME TO THE SAME CONCLUSION.
THEY'LL FALL INTO LINE.
I HAVE ALWAYS BELIEVED THAT
ALL XINDI LONG FOR UNIFICATION.
IT'S IN OUR BLOOD.
I AGREE.
THE EARTH SHIP.
I'M ASSISTING THEM
WITH THEIR ENGINE REPAIRS.
THEY'VE FOUND
QUITE AN ALLY IN YOU.
A PITY YOU HAVEN'T EXTENDED
THE SAME FRIENDSHIP
TO YOUR FELLOW XINDI.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WE RECOVERED A SENSOR ENCODER
FROM OUR MISSING SCOUT SHIP.
IT WAS IN THE CLOAKING BARRIER
OF A SPHERE.
WE WERE ABLE TO EXTRACT
THE FINAL SCANS IT TOOK
BEFORE THEY WERE DESTROYED...
BY YOU.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THE EVIDENCE IS IRREFUTABLE.
WE HAVE AN IMAGE
OF YOUR SHIP FIRING.
DON'T TRY TO DENY WHAT YOU DID.
THEY LEFT ME NO CHOICE.
AND YOU'VE LEFT ME NO CHOICE.
[ GRUNTS ]
THE CREW OF THAT SHIP
ARE THE LAST XINDI
YOU'LL EVER BETRAY.
[ GROANS ]
WHEN THE HUMANS
HAVE BEEN ELIMINATED,
WHEN THE COUNCIL HAS BEEN
REPLACED BY REPTILIAN RULE,
I AM GOING TO FIND
YOUR WIFE AND CHILDREN
AND DO THE SAME TO THEM.
YOUR TRAITOROUS BLOODLINE
WILL END AT THE TIP OF MY BLADE.
TROUBLE SLEEPING?
IT'S WEIRD.
WITH THINGS FINALLY LOOKING UP,
YOU'D THINK I'D BE ABLE
TO GET SOME SHUT-EYE.
THERE'S A SECTION OF MESS HALL
UP AND RUNNING.
IN THE MOOD FOR A SNACK?
CERTAINLY.
I GUESS YOU HEARD.
THE CAPTAIN PULLED IT OFF.
THE XINDI POSTPONED
THE WEAPON LAUNCH.
YOU MAKE THAT
SOUND LIKE BAD NEWS.
EVER SINCE THE ATTACK ON EARTH,
ALL I'VE THOUGHT ABOUT
IS GETTING BACK AT
WHOEVER WAS RESPONSIBLE.
AND NOW WE ARE MAKING PEACE
WITH THEM.
I'VE GOTTEN USED TO THE ANGER.
IT'S GOING TO BE LIKE --
I DON'T KNOW -- LOSING AN OLD
FRIEND.
YOU HAVE OTHER FRIENDS.
IS IT MY IMAGINATION,
OR ARE YOU LOSING WEIGHT?
AH, I WAS HOPING
SOMEONE MIGHT NOTICE.
YEAH, I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE.
HOSHI COMMENTED ON IT LAST WEEK.
WELL, I'M PLEASED TO SEE THAT
MY EFFORTS ARE YIELDING RESULTS.
WHAT'S YOUR SECRET?
A DENAXIAN TAPEWORM.
IT ATTACHES ITSELF
TO THE LOWER INTESTINAL TRACT
AND ABSORBS NUTRIENTS --
HOLD ON, HOLD ON!
YOU HAVE A WORM INSIDE YOU?
IT'S PERFECTLY HARMLESS.
I HARDLY NOTICE IT AT ALL.
HOW ARE YOU GOING TO GET IT OUT?
I INSERT A STANDARD V-PROBE
INTO MY --
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NEVER MIND.
WELL, IT'S A SIMPLE PROCEDURE.
I'M SURE IT IS, DOC.
I JUST DON'T WANT
TO LOSE MY APPETITE.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
DEGRA'S DEAD.
HE WAS FOUND IN HIS QUARTERS
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
HE'D BEEN MURDERED, STABBED.
-WHO DID THIS?
-THE REPTILIANS HAVE CALLED
AN EMERGENCY MEETING
OF THE COUNCIL.
I BELIEVE
THEIR RECENT TURNABOUT
WAS NOTHING MORE THAN A RUSE
TO KEEP US OFF GUARD.
THEY'RE PLANNING SOMETHING.
I'M CERTAIN OF IT.
YOUR SHIP'S IN DANGER.
KEEP ME APPRISED.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
Bridge.
GO TO TACTICAL ALERT.
[ BEEPING ]
IT WAS THAT LAST RUN
THROUGH THE CLOAKING BARRIER.
THE COIL ASSEMBLY'S
BEEN DAMAGED.
REDUCE SPEED.
HOLD AT HALF-IMPULSE.
-AAH!
-LIEUTENANT?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
I'M FINE.
MAYBE THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
MAYBE WE'RE GETTING A BIT TOO
COMFORTABLE WITH LOSING PEOPLE.
23 MEN AND WOMEN.
ON ANY GIVEN MISSION,
THE LIMIT OF ACCEPTABLE
CASUALTIES IS 20%.
SO SAYS TRADITIONAL
MILITARY DOCTRINE.
WELL, WE'VE CROSSED THAT MARGIN.
THERE'S A VULCAN AXIOM --
"THE NEEDS OF THE MANY
OUTWEIGH THE NEEDS OF THE FEW."
CORPORAL HAWKINS
UNDERSTOOD THAT.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE HIS DEATH
ANY MORE ACCEPTABLE.
NO, BUT IT MAKES IT HONORABLE.
YOU ADMIT KILLING HIM?
WITH PRIDE.
HE WAS A TRAITOR.
HE WAS A MEMBER OF THIS COUNCIL!
DEGRA DESTROYED
A REPTILIAN SHIP.
22 CREWMEN DIED.
I ONLY REGRET
NOT DOING IT SOONER.
YOU'RE GOING TO REGRET
A LOT MORE THAN THAT.
WHY DID YOU CALL THIS MEETING?
YOU HAVE A DECISION TO MAKE.
WE'VE TAKEN CONTROL
OF THE WEAPON.
WE'RE GOING TO LAUNCH IT.
AND YOU ACCUSE DEGRA
OF BEING A TRAITOR!
[ CHITTERING ]
EITHER YOU STAND WITH US
OR YOU STAND AGAINST US.
THAT'S NOT A CHOICE.
IT'S AN ULTIMATUM.
CALL IT WHAT YOU WILL.
NEITHER WILL WE.
NONE OF US WILL.
THEN WE WITHDRAW
FROM THIS COUNCIL.
THINK ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE DOING.
THIS ALLIANCE HAS LASTED
FOR DECADES!
IT'S LASTED TOO LONG.
YOU'VE BECOME COMPLACENT.
THE WEAPON CANNOT BE LAUNCHED
WITHOUT THREE OF THE CODES.
YOU ONLY HAVE TWO.
DO YOU REALLY BELIEVE
WE HAVEN'T CONSIDERED THAT?
I CAN GIVE YOU 3.4
WITH A LITTLE COAXING,
BUT SOME OF THE RELAYS
ARE STILL FRIED.
WE'RE IN NO SHAPE FOR COMBAT.
THAT HASN'T STOPPED US
IN THE PAST.
YOU SURE THEY'RE
COMING AFTER US?
COUNT ON IT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I ACTUALLY
FEEL BAD ABOUT DEGRA.
24 HOURS AGO,
I WOULD HAVE BEEN CELEBRATING.
A LOT CAN HAPPEN IN A DAY.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-Bridge to Captain Archer.
-ARCHER.
-Five Insectoid ships
are descending
toward the surface.
[ RUMBLING ]
-REPORT!
-THE WEAPON'S BEEN LAUNCHED
FROM BENEATH THE SURFACE.
THE INSECTOID SHIPS
ARE IN FORMATION AROUND IT.
PURSUIT COURSE!
[ BEEPING ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
THE REPTILIANS AND INSECTOIDS
HAVE SEIZED CONTROL
OF THE WEAPON.
WE'RE TRACKING IT.
I'VE ORDERED ALL AVAILABLE SHIPS
TO INTERCEPT.
WE'RE RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
I HOPE THERE'S SOMETHING
IN THERE YOU CAN USE.
MOST DEFINITELY.
THERE'S A LARGE GROUP
OF SHIPS LEAVING THE SYSTEM
ONE OF THEM IS ENTERPRISE.
I'M DETECTING WEAPONS FIRE.
STAY WITH IT.
KEEP FIRING!
-[ BEEPING ]
-IT'S THE SHUTTLEPOD.
TELL THEM TO STAY PUT.
WE'LL COME BACK FOR THEM
WHEN WE CAN.
OPEN A CHANNEL TO DEGRA'S SHIP.
WE'RE MOVING IN ON THE WEAPON.
CONCENTRATE YOUR FIRE
ON THE PRIMARY GENERATORS
SIX METERS BELOW
THE AFT THRUSTERS.
FORGET THE OTHERS.
TARGET ENTERPRISE.
GET THE FEMALE.
HOSHI!
THEY'RE DISABLED.
THE FEMALE?
GENERATORS AT MAXIMUM POWER.
TAKE US INTO THE VORTEX.
WE'VE LOST THEM, SIR.