T'Pol:
PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
Degra: HOW DO YOU PLAN
TO GET INSIDE IT?
WE'RE PRETTY SURE
WE FOUND A WAY IN.
I'M SENDING
A CREW IN A SHUTTLEPOD.
T'Pol:
THE SPHERES ARE CONTROLLED
BY A NETWORK
OF ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE.
THIS SECTION HOUSES
A REDUNDANT MEMORY CORE.
IT SHOULD CONTAIN A SIGNIFICANT
AMOUNT OF INFORMATION.
Archer: WE'RE HOPING
THAT'LL INCLUDE DATA
ON THE SPHERE BUILDERS.
HAWKINS!
I'LL BE AT YOUR SIDE,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS.
WE'VE TAKEN CONTROL
OF THE WEAPON.
WE'RE GOING TO LAUNCH IT.
WAIT!
UGH!
[ CHATTERS ]
Dolim: WE HAVE AN IMAGE
OF YOUR SHIP FIRING.
THEY LEFT ME NO CHOICE.
AND YOU'VE LEFT ME NO CHOICE.
THE CREW ON THAT SHIP
ARE THE LAST XINDI
YOU'LL EVER BETRAY.
THE WEAPON CANNOT BE LAUNCHED
WITHOUT THREE OF THE CODES.
DO YOU REALLY BELIEVE
WE HAVEN'T CONSIDERED THAT?
HOSHI!
[ GROANS ]
WHY AM I HERE?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WE WERE IMPRESSED
WITH YOUR LINGUISTIC ABILITIES.
AQUATIC IS DIFFICULT TO MASTER.
I'VE HEARD IT SPOKEN
MY ENTIRE LIFE,
BUT STILL
IT DOESN'T COME EASILY TO ME.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD HAVE
APPLIED YOURSELF MORE.
WE HAVE SOME ENCODED DATA
WE NEED TRANSLATED.
I'M NOT A CRYPTOLOGIST.
I HAVE CONFIDENCE
IN YOUR ABILITIES.
THAT'S VERY FLATTERING,
BUT YOU'LL HAVE TO MANAGE
ON YOUR OWN.
IF YOU REFUSE,
WE'LL HAVE NO FURTHER USE
FOR YOU.
GET HER READY
FOR THE PROCEDURE.
[ GRUNTING ]
SHE'S SURPRISINGLY
STRONG-WILLED FOR A PRIMATE.
WE'LL SEE HOW DEFIANT SHE IS
AFTER OUR SURGEONS
HAVE FINISHED WITH HER.
WE'LL HAVE THE LAUNCH CODES
SOON ENOUGH.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
WE NEED TO ACCESS
THE DATA FROM THIS.
MEET ME IN THE COMMAND CENTER
IN HALF AN HOUR.
I'LL ASSIST YOU.
WHAT HAVE WE MISSED?
THE REPTILIANS
TOOK THE WEAPON.
HAVE THEY LAUNCHED IT?
WE DON'T KNOW.
THE CAPTAIN'S ON HIS WAY
TO THE SURFACE,
WANTS TO FIGURE OUT
OUR NEXT MOVE.
AND THEY TOOK HOSHI.
SHE'S GONE.
WHO?
REPTILIANS, INSECTOIDS --
WE DON'T KNOW.
THEY TRANSPORTED HER
OFF THE BRIDGE.
WHERE'S CORPORAL HAWKINS?
THE SPHERE HAD AN AUTOMATED
DEFENSE MECHANISM.
HE WAS KILLED.
I'M SORRY, MAJOR.
I'M SURE YOU DID EVERYTHING
YOU COULD.
I'D APPRECIATE A FULL REPORT.
WHERE ARE THEY?
WE'RE TRYING TO DETERMINE
THEIR LOCATION.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO TRACK THEM
INSIDE A VORTEX.
FOR ALL YOU KNOW, THEY COULD
BE HEADING TO EARTH.
THEY CAN'T DEPLOY
THE WEAPON, NOT YET.
EACH OF THE FIVE SPECIES
HAS A SET OF COMMANDS
TO INITIATE THE ARMING SEQUENCE.
THREE OF THEM ARE NEEDED
TO ACTIVATE THE WEAPON.
Jannar:
THEY ONLY HAVE TWO.
WE OBVIOUSLY DON'T INTEND
TO GIVE THEM OURS.
WHAT ABOUT THE AQUATICS?
THEIR ACTIONS
AREN'T EASY TO PREDICT.
BUT SO FAR, THEY SEEM DETERMINED
NOT TO TAKE SIDES.
IT'S MORE LIKELY
THE REPTILIANS AND INSECTOIDS
WILL ATTEMPT TO BYPASS
THE COMMAND CODES THEMSELVES.
AND THAT WILL TAKE TIME.
THEY'VE ABDUCTED
MY COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER.
UP UNTIL NOW,
I DIDN'T KNOW WHY.
YOU BELIEVE THEY'LL USE HER
TO DECRYPT THE ARMING SEQUENCE?
SHE'LL NEVER COOPERATE.
SHE MAY NOT HAVE A CHOICE.
THIS COULD BE
A COMMAND SUBROUTINE.
AND IT COULD BE
A LETTER TO SANTA CLAUS.
I WOULDN'T MIND HAVING
HOSHI HERE RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL HAVE TO MAKE DO
WITHOUT HER.
Tucker:
I JUST HOPE SHE'S OKAY.
WE'RE HERE TO ANALYZE THIS DATA,
NOT SPECULATE
ON ENSIGN SATO'S FATE.
YOU OKAY?
I'M FOND OF HOSHI AS WELL,
BUT WE CAN'T ALLOW HER SITUATION
TO BECOME A DISTRACTION.
ANY LUCK?
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL
OF DATA TO ANALYZE,
BUT WE'VE MADE SOME PROGRESS.
WE KNOW THE SPHERES
ARE CONNECTED
BY A SUBSPACE ENERGY GRID,
BUT FOUR OF THEM APPEAR TO BE
INTEGRAL TO THAT CONNECTION.
THE CLOSEST ONE'S HERE.
WE'VE DESIGNATED IT SPHERE 41.
INTEGRAL HOW?
I BELIEVE THEY ACT
AS CONTROL SPHERES,
ALLOWING THE NETWORK
TO OPERATE IN CONCERT.
IF WE CAN DAMAGE ONE OF THEM,
WOULD IT DISRUPT
THE ENTIRE GRID?
MAYBE.
IT ALSO MIGHT HAVE NO EFFECT.
WE JUST DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH INFORMATION YET.
KEEP AT IT.
AYE, SIR.
COOPERATE,
AND THIS WON'T BE NECESSARY.
[ GROANING ]
WAIT.
AFTER THE INJECTION,
THE PARASITES
WILL INVADE YOUR NEOCORTEX.
ONCE THEY BEGIN RECONFIGURING
YOUR SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS,
YOU'LL BE MUCH MORE COMPLIANT.
BEFORE YOUR PRIMATE BRAIN
IS TOO BADLY DAMAGED
TO UNDERSTAND,
I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR HELPING
US DESTROY YOUR WORLD.
[ SCREAMING ]
Jannar: IF THEY'D STAYED
IN THE VORTEX,
WE WOULDN'T
HAVE FOUND THEM.
Councilor: THEY'RE LESS THAN
FOUR LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE.
WHY HAVE THEY STOPPED?
THEY COULD'VE BEEN
HALFWAY TO EARTH BY NOW.
THEY'RE ATTEMPTING
TO ARM THE WEAPON.
THE PROPULSION SYSTEM
HAS TO BE OFFLINE TO DO IT.
HOW QUICKLY CAN WE GET THERE?
THAT WOULDN'T BE WISE.
THEY'VE BEEN JOINED
BY AT LEAST A DOZEN VESSELS.
YOU HAVE NEARLY AS MANY SHIPS.
YOU MAY HAVE NOTICED
THAT REPTILIANS AND INSECTOIDS
ARE MORE BELLIGERENT
THAN WE ARE.
THEIR SHIPS
ARE ARMED ACCORDINGLY.
WE'RE NO MATCH FOR THEM.
WE'VE BEEN
OUTGUNNED BEFORE, SIR.
WE DID NOT COME ALL THIS WAY
TO GIVE UP WITHOUT A FIGHT.
WOULD THE AQUATICS
BE A MATCH FOR THEM?
THEIR SHIPS
ARE EXTREMELY POWERFUL,
BUT THEY'VE SEEN
YOUR EVIDENCE.
THEY'RE NOT CONVINCED.
THAT WAS BEFORE
THE REPTILIANS MURDERED DEGRA
AND STOLE THE WEAPON.
WE'RE LOOKING AT CIVIL WAR.
CAN THEY AFFORD TO SIT BACK
AND DO NOTHING?
LET ME TALK TO THEM.
[ BELLOWING ]
NOW ISN'T THE TIME
TO DISSOLVE THE COUNCIL.
[ AQUATICS BELLOWING ]
SO WE SHOULD LEAVE
OUR FATE IN THE HANDS
OF THE REPTILIANS
AND INSECTOIDS?
[ AQUATICS BELLOWING ]
I DISAGREE.
THE EVIDENCE
THE HUMANS PROVIDED
CAN'T BE IGNORED.
[ AQUATICS BELLOWING ]
I DIDN'T QUITE CATCH
THAT LAST PART.
THEY'VE AGREED
TO MEET WITH US.
[ SIGHS ]
BUT DON'T EXPECT MUCH,
CAPTAIN.
HOW LONG DO THEY PLAN
TO KEEP US WAITING?
WE'LL HAVE TO DEAL WITH
THE AQUATICS ON THEIR TERMS.
THEY'RE EXTREMELY DELIBERATE
IN EVERYTHING THEY DO.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
MY SPECIES
DOESN'T LIKE THE WATER.
THEY'RE HERE.
THANK YOU FOR SEEING ME.
I'M AFRAID
MY COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER
WAS ABDUCTED BY THE REPTILIANS.
Female Aquatics councilor:
THAT IS REGRETTABLE,
BUT HER PRESENCE
IS NO LONGER NECESSARY.
WE'VE HAD TIME TO STUDY
YOUR LANGUAGE.
THEN I'LL GET TO THE POINT.
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
Male Aquatics councilor:
WE'VE MADE OUR POSITION CLEAR.
YOUR EVIDENCE IS INTRIGUING
BUT FAR FROM CONCLUSIVE.
Female councilor: WE REQUIRE
MORE TIME TO EVALUATE IT.
AND IF MY WORLD GETS TORN
TO RUBBLE IN THE MEANTIME?
Female councilor: THE REPTILIANS
AND THE INSECTOIDS
CANNOT DEPLOY THE WEAPON
ON THEIR OWN.
THAT MAY NOT BE TRUE.
I BELIEVE THEY TOOK MY OFFICER
TO HELP THEM DECIPHER
A THIRD LAUNCH CODE.
AFTER ALL YOUR DELIBERATIONS,
YOU MAY FIND A DECISION'S
BEEN MADE WITHOUT YOU.
Male councilor:
THIS CHANGES NOTHING.
Female councilor:
JUST BECAUSE THE REPTILIANS
CHOOSE TO ACT RASHLY
DOES NOT MEAN
WE WILL DO THE SAME.
SO YOU'D RATHER SIT BACK
AND DO NOTHING...
CAPTAIN.
...WHILE THEY CONDEMN ALL FIVE
OF YOUR SPECIES TO EXTINCTION!
Male councilor:
YOU MAY RETURN TO YOUR SHIP.
YOU WILL BE INFORMED
OF OUR DECISION.
ONE LAST QUESTION.
HAVE THESE GUARDIANS TOLD YOU
WHERE YOU'LL ESTABLISH
YOUR NEW HOMEWORLD?
THE ONE HUMANS
ARE DESTINED TO DESTROY?
IS IT HERE, IN THE EXPANSE?
IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
THE SPHERES ARE TURNING IT
INTO A TRANS-DIMENSIONAL
WASTELAND.
NONE OF YOU
WILL BE ABLE TO SURVIVE.
YOU SAY
THE GUARDIANS HAVE HELPED YOU.
HAVE THEY EVER TRIED
TO DISABLE THE SPHERES?
BECAUSE WE'VE FOUND A WAY.
HELP ME SAVE MY PEOPLE,
AND I CAN HELP YOU SAVE YOURS.
REPORT.
SHE'S PENETRATED
THE FIRST LAYER OF ENCRYPTION.
NOTHING FURTHER.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT WE WANT YOU TO DO?
I'M TO BYPASS THE AQUATIC
ENCRYPTION PROTOCOLS.
AND YOU REALIZE
WE NEED THIS DONE QUICKLY.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH THESE CIPHERS.
I'M TRYING.
ARE YOU?
[ GRUNTS ]
[ HISSES ]
UGH!
SHE'S MORE RESISTANT
THAN I IMAGINED.
PREPARE HER
FOR ANOTHER PROCEDURE.
[ SATO GRUNTING ]
YOU WOULD SACRIFICE YOURSELF
TO STOP US.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU WON'T HAVE TO LIVE
WITH YOUR GUILT FOR LONG.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
COMMANDER, I CAN'T ACCESS
THE ARMING MATRIX.
SHE'S ADDED
A LAYER OF ENCRYPTION!
YOU WERE ORDERED TO WATCH HER.
[ HISSING ]
T'Pol: A DEFLECTOR PULSE MIGHT
DISRUPT THE SUBSPACE LINKS.
IT WOULDN'T GENERATE
ENOUGH POWER.
WE COULD TIE
THE IMPULSE REACTORS
DIRECTLY INTO THE ARRAY.
SURE, IF YOU WANT TO RUPTURE
EVERY E.P.S. CONDUIT
ON THE SHIP.
THE CAPTAIN TOLD THE AQUATICS
WE COULD DISABLE
THESE SPHERES.
AND I'M TRYING NOT TO MAKE
A LIAR OUT OF HIM.
REALLY?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT?
YOU'VE DISMISSED
ALL OF MY PROPOSALS.
WHEN YOU COME UP WITH ONE
THAT DOESN'T INVOLVE
BLOWING OURSELVES UP,
I'LL BE A LITTLE MORE
ENTHUSIASTIC.
OR YOU MIGHT SURPRISE ME
WITH AN IDEA OF YOUR OWN.
MAYBE YOU HAVEN'T HAD TIME
TO MEDITATE. I DON'T KNOW.
BUT WHATEVER'S GOING ON
WITH YOU LATELY,
I'VE HAD ABOUT ENOUGH.
I'LL WORK ON THIS
IN ENGINEERING.
CALL ME IF YOU HAVE
ANY MORE BRILLIANT IDEAS.
COMMANDER.
TRIP!
EVERYTHING
THAT'S HAPPENED RECENTLY
HAS CAUSED ME TO BECOME...
SLIGHTLY EMOTIONAL.
I'VE NOTICED.
I APOLOGIZE.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
I WISH I COULD.
IT MAY TAKE SOME TIME
BEFORE I REGAIN MY CONTROL.
IT WILL BE DIFFICULT TO DO,
ESPECIALLY...ON MY OWN.
THIS HASN'T BEEN EASY
FOR ANY OF US.
YOU KNOW HOW MUCH I APPRECIATE
WHAT YOU DID FOR ME.
WHEN THIS IS ALL OVER,
IF YOU WANT TO TALK,
I'M ALL EARS.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE
ANOTHER CRACK AT THIS?
THE COUNCIL HAS DISBANDED.
THE WEAPON
IS UNDER OUR CONTROL.
EXCELLENT.
DEPLOY IT IMMEDIATELY.
AS SOON AS WE DECRYPT
THE THIRD LAUNCH CODE.
WE'VE ENCOUNTERED
SOME DIFFICULTIES.
THE LONGER YOU DELAY,
THE MORE LIKELY THE TIMELINES
WILL SHIFT AGAINST YOU.
THEN PERHAPS YOU COULD PROVIDE
MORE OF YOUR
VALUABLE ASSISTANCE.
HELP US GET THE CODE.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
IT SHOULD BE A SIMPLE MATTER
TO PEER INTO THE PAST,
EXTRACT THE NECESSARY DATA.
WE ONLY DETECT LARGE
FLUCTUATIONS IN THE TIMESCAPE.
THE FINE DETAILS ARE OBSCURED.
REALLY?
YOU'VE SEEN MORE
THAN ENOUGH DETAIL
TO LEARN HOW TO MEDDLE
IN OUR AFFAIRS
TO TURN THE XINDI SPECIES
AGAINST EACH OTHER.
EVERYTHING WE'VE DONE
HAS BEEN TO PROTECT THE XINDI.
THEN FINISH
WHAT YOU'VE STARTED...
IF IT'S WITHIN YOUR POWER.
THE TIMELINES
ARE IN CONSTANT FLUX.
MANY OF THEM FAVOR THE PRIMATES
AND THE ARBOREALS.
SOME EVEN FAVOR THE HUMANS.
UNLESS THAT'S THE OUTCOME
YOU DESIRE,
I SUGGEST YOU FIND A WAY
TO LAUNCH THE WEAPON.
THIS APPEARS TO BE SOME KIND
OF INTERSPATIAL MANIFOLD
ON THE SURFACE OF SPHERE 41.
WHAT THEY USE
TO CONNECT THE SPHERES.
Tucker:
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE THINKING.
T'POL'S FIGURED OUT A WAY
TO TARGET IT
WITH A DEFLECTOR PULSE.
WELL DONE.
WE HAVEN'T EXACTLY GOT ALL
THE DETAILS WORKED OUT YET.
THEN YOU'D BETTER KEEP AT IT.
IF THE AQUATICS
DECIDE TO HELP US,
THEY MIGHT WANT TO HEAR
THOSE DETAILS.
Tucker: CAPTAIN.
HOPE YOU DIDN'T MAKE THEM
ANY PROMISES.
WE'LL KEEP WORKING.
PLEASE DO.
ANY WORD?
IT'S ONLY BEEN THREE HOURS.
THE COUNCIL
ONCE NEEDED TO RESOLVE
A SIMPLE LOGISTICAL MATTER.
IT TOOK THE AQUATICS SIX DAYS
TO AGREE TO ATTEND THE MEETING.
I'M SURPRISED
YOU WERE EVER ABLE
TO GET ANYTHING DONE.
ON THE CONTRARY,
THEIR PRUDENCE
WAS USUALLY THE ONLY THING
THAT KEPT THE COUNCIL
FROM DISSOLVING INTO CHAOS.
THAT'S WHY DEGRA HAD THEM
BUILD THE WEAPON.
HE DIDN'T WANT
THE REPTILIANS AND INSECTOIDS
TO HAVE TOO MUCH CONTROL.
THAT'S ACTUALLY SOMETHING
I WANTED TO DISCUSS WITH YOU.
IF WE'RE SUCCESSFUL,
AND WE DESTROY THE WEAPON...
WHAT'S TO PREVENT US
FROM BUILDING ANOTHER ONE?
I KNEW DEGRA FOR MANY YEARS.
HE COULD BE DIFFICULT,
UNCOMPROMISING.
WE ARGUED OFTEN --
FOR INSTANCE, WHEN HE INSISTED
THAT WE MEET WITH YOU.
BUT WHEN DEGRA SPOKE,
ONLY A FOOL WOULD IGNORE HIM.
HE BELIEVED THERE WAS A FUTURE
BETWEEN YOUR PEOPLE AND OURS.
WHEN THIS IS OVER,
I INTEND TO SEE IF HE WAS RIGHT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
REED: Captain Archer,
please report to the bridge.
REPORT.
SIX VESSELS APPROACHING, SIR,
ALL AQUATIC.
THAT WAS REMARKABLY FAST.
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO THE LEAD SHIP.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Male councilor:
WE'VE CONSIDERED YOUR PROPOSAL.
AND?
Female councilor: WE WILL HELP
YOU INTERCEPT THE WEAPON.
THANK YOU.
Female councilor: WE EXPECT YOU
TO HONOR OUR AGREEMENT.
Male councilor: YOU WILL
ATTEMPT TO DISABLE THE SPHERES.
HOW DO THESE DEVELOPMENTS
AFFECT THE TIMELINE?
IT'S DIFFICULT TO SAY.
THEY CONTINUE TO FLUCTUATE.
HOWEVER, MOST NOW INDICATE
THE HUMANS WILL PREVAIL.
THEN THE TIME HAS COME
FOR US TO INTERVENE.
IS THERE ANOTHER PROBLEM?
QUITE THE OPPOSITE.
THE THIRD LAUNCH CODE.
WE HAVE COMPLETE ACCESS.
IT APPEARS THE PRIMATE
WAS USEFUL AFTER ALL.
TAKE HER BACK TO HER CELL.
INITIATE
THE PRE-ARMING PROTOCOLS.
INFORM ME WHEN THE WEAPON
IS READY FOR LAUNCH.
Archer: CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
FEBRUARY 13, 2154.
WE'RE PREPARING TO ENTER
A XINDI VORTEX,
THANKS TO SOME HELP
FROM THE AQUATICS.
IF EVERYTHING GOES AS PLANNED,
WE'LL INTERCEPT THE WEAPON
IN LESS THAN TWO HOURS.
ENTERPRISE MAY BE COMING APART
AT THE SEAMS,
BUT I CAN'T SAY THE SAME
FOR THE CREW.
AFTER NEARLY EIGHT MONTHS
IN THE EXPANSE,
THEY'RE READY TO DO
WHAT THEY CAME TO DO,
NO MATTER WHAT IT TAKES,
NO MATTER WHAT THE COST.
HAVE YOU ASSEMBLED
YOUR BOARDING PARTY?
READY TO DEPLOY
ON YOUR COMMAND.
I WISH
I WAS LEADING IT MYSELF.
YOUR PLACE
IS ON THE BRIDGE, SIR.
NO OFFENSE, MAJOR.
IT'S JUST THAT ENSIGN SATO
IS A FRIEND.
THERE'S MY REPORT
ON CORPORAL HAWKINS.
THANK YOU.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO GO OVER
MY RESCUE PLAN?
FIRST, I'D LIKE TO KNOW
IF WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
SIR?
IF YOU BLAME ME
FOR THE CORPORAL'S DEATH.
PERMISSION TO SPEAK FREELY?
I'VE NEVER LIKED
PUTTING MY PEOPLE
UNDER SOMEONE ELSE'S
COMMAND.
YOU'RE SENIOR
TACTICAL OFFICER,
BUT THEY'RE MY TEAM.
I CAN'T HELP BUT THINK
THAT IF I'D BEEN THERE,
THINGS MIGHT HAVE
TURNED OUT DIFFERENTLY.
I DID EVERYTHING I COULD.
THINGS HAPPENED VERY FAST.
-I UNDERSTAND.
-I'M NOT FINISHED.
HAWKINS MAY WELL
HAVE BEEN A MACO,
BUT HE WAS MY RESPONSIBILITY
OUT THERE.
WHEN WE FIRST CAME
ABOARD ENTERPRISE,
WE DEFINITELY FELT
LIKE OUTSIDERS.
IF I CONTRIBUTED TO THAT,
I APOLOGIZE --
MY POINT IS...
NONE OF US
FEEL THAT WAY ANYMORE.
WE'RE ALL PART
OF THE SAME CREW,
NO MATTER
WHICH UNIFORM WE WEAR.
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT ENSIGN SATO.
WE'LL BRING HER HOME.
[ PORTHOS WHIMPERS ]
MMM.
I'D ALMOST FORGOTTEN
WHAT CHEF CAN DO WITH A STEAK.
I HOPE THE CREW FORGIVES ME
FOR NOT PATCHING UP
THE GALLEY SOONER.
I'VE HEARD NO COMPLAINTS...
EXCEPT FROM CHEF, OF COURSE.
YOU KNOW, WHEN THIS IS
ALL OVER,
I PLAN ON HAVING A LITTLE CHAT
WITH THE STARFLEET QUARTERMASTER
ABOUT WHAT THEY PUT
IN THOSE RATION PACKS.
WHEN THIS IS ALL OVER, I WON'T
BE COMPLAINING ABOUT THE FOOD.
I'LL JUST BE HAPPY TO GET BACK
TO OUR ORIGINAL MISSION.
HOPE YOU'RE PLANNING
ON SWINGING BY EARTH FIRST.
I TOLD THE ENGINEERING TEAM
I'D BUY THEM A FEW ROUNDS
AT THE 602 CLUB.
YOU'RE BOTH INVITED,
OF COURSE.
I WOULDN'T MISS IT.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU MAY BUY ME A DRINK,
IF YOU WISH.
[ LAUGHS ]
I MEANT WHAT ARE YOUR PLANS
FOR THE FUTURE?
BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE YOU'VE BEEN TO VULCAN.
THE HIGH COMMAND WOULD BE LUCKY
TO GET YOU BACK.
THERE ARE SOME COLLEAGUES
I'D ENJOY SEEING AGAIN.
BUT I'VE CONSIDERED FORMALIZING
MY SERVICE WITH STARFLEET.
I MAY BE ABLE
TO PULL SOME STRINGS,
GET YOU OUT OF BASIC TRAINING.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THE LOOK
ON SOVAL'S FACE
WHEN HE SEES HER
IN A STARFLEET UNIFORM?
-[ LAUGHS ]
-PLEASE LET ME BE THERE.
I SAID I WAS CONSIDERING IT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
REED:
Bridge to the Captain.
GO AHEAD.
We're approaching
the coordinates.
TACTICAL ALERT.
I'M ON MY WAY.
ACTIVATE THE REACTOR.
Soldier:
YES, LIEUTENANT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
COMMANDER DOLIM,
the final arming sequence
has begun.
EXCELLENT.
INFORM ME WHEN YOU ARE READY.
I'LL BE
IN MY THERMAL CHAMBER.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
A VORTEX IS OPENING.
WHERE?
BEARING 279,
RANGE 4,000 KILOMETERS.
WERE YOU EXPECTING
REINFORCEMENTS?
NO.
ARBOREALS.
SEND A PATROL
TO INTERCEPT THEM.
MORE VORTEXES ARE OPENING.
14 -- 18 SHIPS.
AQUATICS. SIX SHIPS
APPROACHING THE WEAPON.
TARGET THEM!
HAVE COMMANDER KOLO'S SQUADRON
MAINTAIN POSITION.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THEY'RE MOVING TO INTERCEPT,
BUT THEY'RE KEEPING
A SUBSTANTIAL FORCE
AROUND THE WEAPON.
FEEL LIKE
TAKING THEM ON?
GIVE ME THE WORD, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
CUT US LOOSE.
SIR, THE HUMANS.
STEADY, TRAVIS.
THEY'RE BREAKING OFF.
HAVE ALL SHIPS CONCENTRATE
THEIR FIRE ON THE WEAPON.
WE'RE IN RANGE.
FIRE.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
THEY'RE TARGETING
THE PRIMARY GENERATORS.
CONTINUE THE ARMING SEQUENCE.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
MINOR DAMAGE
TO THE STARBOARD NACELLE.
WE'RE STILL IN THE FIGHT.
BRING US AROUND
FOR ANOTHER PASS.
TARGET THE EARTH VESSEL!
WE CAN'T, SIR. THE AQUATICS
ARE PROTECTING THEM.
CAPTAIN,
I'VE LOCATED ENSIGN SATO.
SHE'S ONBOARD ONE
OF THE REPTILIAN VESSELS.
CAN YOU GET
A TRANSPORTER LOCK?
SHE'S SOMEWHERE
ON THE FIRST THREE DECKS.
I CAN'T PINPOINT
HER EXACT LOCATION.
SEND MAJOR HAYES
AND HIS TEAM.
AYE, SIR.
Soldier:
WE'VE LOST EIGHT VESSELS.
WE'VE ONLY DISABLED
TWO OF THEIRS.
WE'RE NO MATCH
FOR THE AQUATICS.
LIEUTENANT!
We must deploy
the weapon now.
WE NEED
ANOTHER FIVE MINUTES.
IN ANOTHER FIVE MINUTES,
IT WILL BE DESTROYED,
and you along with it!
[ GROANS ]
UGH!
ENSIGN.
HAYES TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, RESPOND.
WE SHOULD GET BACK
TO THE BEAM-IN POINT.
[ GRUNTS ]
THE REPTILIANS ARE UNDER ATTACK.
IF WE DON'T ACT,
THE WEAPON WILL BE DESTROYED.
THE TIMELINES NOW INDICATE
THAT IS THE LIKELY OUTCOME.
PROCEED.
[ GRUNTS ]
CAPTAIN, THERE'S A MASSIVE
ANOMALY FORMING NEAR THE WEAPON.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
TWO MORE.
KEEP US CLEAR OF THEM, TRAVIS.
WE'LL HAVE TO PULL BACK.
DO WHAT YOU CAN,
BUT KEEP US IN FIRING RANGE.
AYE, SIR.
-CAPTAIN ARCHER!
-Go ahead.
THE ANOMALIES
ARE CREATING A BARRIER
BETWEEN US AND THE WEAPON.
We can't get through.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
HAYES TO ENTERPRISE!
GO AHEAD.
We've got Sato!
ARCHER TO TUCKER.
LOCK ON TO MAJOR HAYES.
I WISH I COULD, SIR.
THAT LAST ANOMALY KNOCKED
THE TRANSPORTER OFFLINE.
TELL THEM TO STAND BY!
ARCHER TO HAYES.
WE'VE GOT A MALFUNCTION.
CAN YOU HOLD YOUR POSITION?
AFFIRMATIVE.
THE INTRUDERS ARE TRAPPED
ON LEVEL SEVEN.
AND THE ANOMALIES?
THEY'VE DISABLED
THREE OF THE AQUATIC SHIPS.
THE GUARDIANS
WILL NOT LET US FAIL.
TUCKER TO HAYES.
-Go ahead.
-I'M READY TO GET YOU OUT.
BUT I CAN ONLY TRANSPORT
TWO AT A TIME.
Then I have to reset the buffer.
TAKE HER.
LOCK ON KELLY AND SATO.
UGH!
TUCKER:
Ready for two more.
YOU TWO ARE NEXT.
[ GROANS ]
I COULD USE
A CHANGE OF SCENERY!
TUCKER:
Stand by, Major.
[ GROANING ]
COMMANDER DOLIM.
DOLIM:
What's your status?
WE'VE COMPLETED
THE ARMING SEQUENCE.
T'Pol: CAPTAIN.
THE POWER READINGS FROM
THE WEAPON ARE INCREASING.
THEY'RE PREPARING TO LAUNCH.
GET US CLOSE, TRAVIS.
WHAT ABOUT THE ANOMALIES?
I SAID TAKE US IN.
AYE, SIR.
READY TO LAUNCH
ON YOUR ORDER, COMMANDER.
OPEN A VORTEX.
SET A COURSE FOR EARTH.
Reed: THEY'RE GONE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
DOCTOR.
I TOLD HIM
I WAS READY FOR DUTY.
I'M AFRAID
HE'S A BIT OF A MOTHER HEN.
[ CHUCKLES, SIGHS ]
HOW'S ENSIGN SATO?
HER BIO-SIGNS ARE STABLE.
THANK YOU
FOR BRINGING HER HOME.
ALL IN A DAY'S WORK.
USE McKENZIE.
WHAT?
SHE KNOWS THE TEAM.
RELY ON HER.
NO MORE OF THAT TALK.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
CARDIO STIMULATOR.
STEP AWAY, PLEASE.
INCREASE BY .2 JOULES.
[ DEFIBRILLATOR ZAPS ]
[ FLATLINE ]
HOW LONG
BEFORE IT REACHES EARTH?
10 HOURS.
COULD AN AQUATIC SHIP
REACH IT IN TIME?
DOUBTFUL.
THEY HAVE POWERFUL WEAPONS,
BUT THEIR SPEED IS LIMITED.
DEGRA'S SHIP
IS CONSIDERABLY FASTER.
WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
THE SHIP ISN'T WELL-ARMED.
IT WOULD BE USELESS
AGAINST THE WEAPON.
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO GET A TEAM ONBOARD,
DISABLE IT FROM THE INSIDE.
THE REPTILIANS
WILL HAVE SOLDIERS
STATIONED ABOARD THE WEAPON.
WE'LL DEAL WITH THEM
WHEN WE GET THERE.
CAPTAIN,
THE AQUATICS JOINED US
ONLY BECAUSE YOU PROMISED
TO NEUTRALIZE THE SPHERES.
THEY EXPECT YOU
TO FULFILL THAT PROMISE.
THE FUTURE OF OUR PEOPLE
IS AT STAKE AS WELL.
ARE YOU READY?
I BELIEVE SO.
WE HAVE A PLAN
TO DISABLE SPHERE 41.
IF WE'RE RIGHT, IT SHOULD
DISRUPT THE ENTIRE NETWORK.
THEN AS SOON AS WE UNDOCK,
SET A COURSE FOR SPHERE 41.
AT EASE.
I'VE JUST COME FROM SICK BAY,
WHERE THE DOCTOR ASSURES ME
THAT SERGEANT KEMPER
AND ENSIGN SATO
WILL MAKE FULL RECOVERIES.
UNFORTUNATELY, MAJOR HAYES'
INJURIES WERE MORE SEVERE.
HE DIDN'T SURVIVE.
I'M SORRY.
WE'VE GOT LESS THAN 10 HOURS
BEFORE THIS WEAPON
REACHES EARTH.
THE CAPTAIN WANTS TO TAKE
A TEAM ABOARD TO DESTROY IT.
I DON'T IMAGINE THE REPTILIANS
WILL MAKE THIS EASY FOR US.
BUT THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE.
THAT'S WHY MAJOR HAYES PICKED
EACH ONE OF YOU
FOR THIS MISSION --
BECAUSE HE KNEW
YOU'D GET THE JOB DONE.
I NEED THREE VOLUNTEERS.
WOODS, RAMIRA, FORBES.
ASSEMBLE YOUR GEAR.
MEET ME AT THE STARBOARD AIRLOCK
IN 10 MINUTES.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HOW IS SHE?
STABLE.
THE XINDI PARASITES WERE
NO MATCH FOR MY OSMOTIC EEL.
I NEED TO TALK TO HER.
SHE'S UNDERGONE
A SEVERE NEURAL TRAUMA.
SHE'S BEEN INSIDE THE WEAPON.
I HAVE TO KNOW WHAT SHE SAW.
IT SHOULD BE SAFE
TO REVIVE HER
IN TWO HOURS, NO LESS.
ALL RIGHT.
HAVE HER TAKEN ABOARD
DEGRA'S SHIP RIGHT AWAY.
SHE'S IN NO CONDITION
TO BE MOVED!
I DON'T HAVE
ANY CHOICE, DOCTOR.
YOU COULD KILL HER.
I WANT HER ON THAT SHIP
IN 20 MINUTES.
SHE'LL NEED ANOTHER
CORTICAL TREATMENT.
AT LEAST LET ME COME WITH YOU.
THERE'S A MEDICAL BAY
ABOARD DEGRA'S SHIP.
SHOW LIEUTENANT REED
HOW TO DO IT.
-HE'S NOT A DOCTOR!
-PHLOX!
YOU'RE NEEDED HERE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THE INSECTOIDS.
[ IN ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
THE ANOMALIES WORKED
TO OUR ADVANTAGE.
WE WERE FORTUNATE.
IT WAS MORE THAN GOOD FORTUNE.
THE HUMAN CLAIMS THE GUARDIANS
CONTROL THE SPHERES.
HE ALSO STARTED A CIVIL WAR
BETWEEN OUR SPECIES.
THE HUMAN DIDN'T KILL DEGRA.
YOU DID.
DEGRA WAS A TRAITOR.
I'M NO LONGER CERTAIN OF THAT.
THEN IT'S A GOOD THING WE
ALREADY HAVE YOUR LAUNCH CODES.
LOCK WEAPONS ON THEIR SHIP.
SIR?
I WON'T RISK
ANY MORE INTERFERENCE.
FIRE.
Tucker:
MALCOLM. HANG ON.
BRING ME BACK
A PIECE OF THAT WEAPON.
A SOUVENIR.
WITH PLEASURE.
ALL SET, SIR.
WHEN WE'RE FINISHED,
WE'LL MEET YOU
AT THE RENDEZVOUS COORDINATES.
WE'LL BE THERE. CAPTAIN!
GOOD LUCK.
I EXPECT YOU
TO KEEP HIM IN LINE.
I'LL DO MY BEST.