T'POL: Previously on Enterprise...
I've located Ensign Sato.
She's onboard one
of the Reptilian vessels.
( screaming )
The third launch code.
We have complete access.
( groans )
The guardians will not let us fail.
The power readings from
the weapon are increasing.
They're preparing to launch.
Open a vortex. Set a course for Earth.
The Captain wants
to take a team aboard to destroy it.
I need three volunteers.
She's undergone a severe neural trauma.
She's been inside the weapon.
I have to know what she saw.
Have her taken aboard
Degra's ship right away.
MAN: The Aquatics joined us
only because you promised
to neutralize the spheres.
We have a plan to disable Sphere 41.
If we're right,
it should disrupt the entire network.
Reptilians will preside
over a stronger, unified Xindi empire
if humankind is eradicated.
If they had made us
the dominant species before the wars,
our homeworld would still exist.
And our avian brothers
would still fill the skies.
We should be grateful that the guardians
have finally come to their senses.
Once Earth is destroyed,
the reptilians
will take their rightful place
at the head of a new Xindi empire.
( mice squeaking )
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And I will see my dream
come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna
change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart
will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength
of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend
or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got, I've got ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
They're nearly three hours ahead of us,
but this vessel is faster.
We're closing the gap.
It may be faster, but it's not well-armed.
How many ships are escorting the weapon?
I can't tell.
The only way we're going to be
able to destroy this thing
is from inside.
Any luck?
All of Degra's schematics are encrypted.
We're gonna need Hoshi to help us.
She's in no condition to come up here.
I wish I had a choice, Malcolm.
Sir, she's barely conscious.
Can you transfer that to a PADD?
Something portable?
The favorable timelines
continue to diminish.
They should be increasing.
The weapon has almost reached its target.
But the Earth ship is on course
for our primary sphere.
Accelerate the transformation
around that sphere.
They mustn't be allowed to intervene.
Report.
We've realigned the main power grid.
It should increase the deflector
pulse threefold, maybe four.
But it's gonna fry just about
every system onboard.
Be prepared to initiate
the pulse within two hours.
I don't think you heard what I just said.
We try this, and the ship's
gonna come apart at the seams.
Two hours, Mr. Tucker.
The Captain told the Xindi
we'd try to knock these things out.
He didn't say anything about
demolishing Enterprise in the process.
Has it occurred to you
what's going to happen
if Captain Archer fails,
if Earth is destroyed?
-Every day.
-Good.
Then you've already come to the conclusion
that without humanity,
there's no one to combat
these sphere builders.
Their expanse will continue to grow,
encompassing one system after another,
including Vulcan.
Your world is no longer
the only one in jeopardy.
Two hours.
( sighs )
( computer beeping )
I think we've got a problem.
What is it?
Sphere 41.
Are you certain these are the coordinates?
Yep.
There shouldn't be anything on sensors,
not with the cloaking barrier.
But there it is and it's getting bigger.
Have you analyzed it?
Could be spatial anomalies,
but they're clustered much tighter
than we've ever seen them.
PHLOX: They're transforming the space
surrounding that sphere,
not unlike the disturbance
where we found
the trans-dimensional being.
They're obviously expecting us.
If we're going to disable the network,
we'll need to get within
a kilometer of the surface.
If the ship were to enter
that disturbance,
the entire crew would be dead
within minutes.
I could synthesize a neuroleptic compound
that would keep us conscious
for approximately 12 minutes.
I'm afraid there's nothing I can do
to prevent epidermal decay.
Twelve minutes won't be enough.
Perhaps I can extend it, but not by much.
I encourage you and Mr. Tucker
to consider alternatives.
There must be something
you can do to abbreviate your plan.
Any luck?
Ensign?
I'm not feeling very well.
Do you think you can get Phlox
to come down here?
We're on Degra's ship, Hoshi.
Phlox isn't here.
I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to be doing.
The schematics for the weapon.
Degra encrypted them before he was killed.
You've been trying to decipher them.
I gave them the third code.
They wouldn't have
been able to arm the weapon
if I hadn't given them the third code.
You were drugged, Hoshi.
You had no choice.
I did. I should have fought harder.
You need to finish what you're doing.
You're almost there.
We're gonna board the weapon,
try to overload the power systems.
But we can't do that
until we can read these schematics.
I tried to jump but I wasn't fast enough.
You need to finish this.
You got the three codes,
so why don't you just kill me?
Didn't you say you were gonna kill me?
You got to pull yourself together
just for a little while longer.
You need to complete the decryption.
Everything hinges on it.
Do you understand?
I understand.
When we exit the vortex,
how close will we be?
Approximately two million kilometers
from Earth.
Two million?
If we had all five codes,
we could begin that
firing sequence immediately.
But with three,
we'll need additional time.
We'd be vulnerable if we dropped
into normal space
any closer to the target.
Do whatever it takes
to fire the weapon as quickly as possible.
You wanted to see me, sir?
I think I found a way to boost
the deflector pulse
without tearing the ship apart.
But it's gonna mean transferring
all impulse power to the array.
When?
As soon as we reach the sphere.
Sir.
Sorry, Travis.
You're gonna have to get us
to the manifold on thrusters only.
That's tying my hands, Commander,
especially with a ticking clock.
You can do it.
Look over these schematics.
Familiarize yourself with
the surface features of the sphere.
We won't be out to transport directly
onto the control platform.
It's too heavily shielded.
We'll have to beam in and out
no deeper than this peripheral framework.
What if you need to board the weapon
before your crewman
completes her decryptions?
I'm taking her with me.
-Sir, she's hardly in any shape--
-She's been there, Malcolm.
That's where she deciphered
the third launch code.
She was drugged.
There's no reason to believe that
she'll remember anything--
ARCHER: She's coming with me.
I want you and your team
to beam in right before we do.
Secure the closest route to the platform.
If you succeed in creating the overload,
what makes you think you'll be
able to get out in time?
I'll give everyone a chance
to get to the outer framework.
You'll be in charge of helping Hoshi.
And you, sir?
I have no plans of dying
on that weapon, Malcolm.
I'm gonna see
what else she's come up with.
DANIELS:
This is a very important day, Jonathan.
-I don't have time for this.
-It'll only take a minute.
You see the fellow in the blue jacket,
near the left end of the dais?
That's you,
a little more than seven years from now.
You and the others
are about to make history.
Do you remember I told you
about a federation?
What about it?
I work with some people
who are going to be
pretty angry at me for telling you this,
but you're going to be an integral part
of forming that federation.
You're down there right now,
with Vulcans, Andorians, and Tellarites,
getting ready to sign the charter.
The membership is going to grow...
dozens, eventually hundreds of species.
A united federation of planets.
I have a team preparing
to board the weapon.
I've got other things
to think about right now.
Let Reed or one of the others
go to the control platform.
-What are you talking about?
-It's too great a risk.
If you're killed,
none of this will happen...
At least,
not the way it's supposed to happen.
Then it'll happen some other way.
Who's to say whether
it'll be better or worse?
It's essential you be a part of this.
Where are we?
-What planet?
-Earth.
Seems to me it's just as essential
that Earth be around for this, too.
Lieutenant Reed can work with Sato.
( applause )
They are not crucial
to the future of mankind.
You are.
My mission is to save Earth,
not your federation.
You can't ignore your place in history.
My place is on that control platform.
Now get me the hell back to Degra's ship.
And if it's not too much
of an inconvenience,
I'd appreciate it if you'd contact
my first wife's third husband, Groznik.
Uh, tell him that he's welcome to keep
the Aldebaran drum set I loaned him.
Oh, they have a child named Indaura.
Sweet little girl...
She must be, uh, 8 or 9 by now.
( laughs )
Well, I would like to leave her
my botanical library.
She always had a flair for plants.
Computer, pause recording.
Everything's ready here.
( clears throat )
Commander Tucker has completed
his modifications to the deflector.
I apologize if I interrupted you.
Oh, no, no, don't be silly.
I was simply dictating a letter
to my colleague, Dr. Lucas.
He offered to make sure my affairs
were in order in the event that, uh...
Well, you know. ( chuckles )
I've always found it distracting
to think of death,
especially when entering
a dangerous situation.
Hmm. Hope for the best,
prepare for the worst.
I don't know about Vulcans,
but Denobulans take great pleasure
in bequeathing their belongings
to far-flung relatives.
We're not dead yet.
-( computer beeps )
-MAN: Bridge to T'Pol.
Go ahead.
We're approaching the coordinates.
Take us out of warp.
Hope for the best, Doctor.
-( computer beeping )
-TRAVIS: It's grown.
It's 100,000 kilometers deeper
than when we first detected it.
I've enhanced the neuroleptic
compound as much as I can.
I strongly advise we remain
in the disturbance
no longer than 15 minutes.
Are you ready to release the compound?
Then proceed.
Stand by to charge the deflector.
Set a course, Ensign.
ARCHER: Captain's starlog, supplemental.
We've begun to formulate a plan,
thanks to Hoshi,
who's made some progress
in decrypting the schematics.
What have you guys figured out?
ARCHER: We've got to disable
the reactor at a specific point
during the inversion sequence,
but we don't know the sequence.
If it's not done in the right order,
the internal safeguards will kick in,
and it'll be impossible
to create an overload.
I found the sequence,
but decrypting it is another story.
Your friend Degra didn't make this easy.
I wish I could tell you to take your time.
The first time you came
to visit me in Brazil...
It didn't stop raining for a week.
I had a bug then too.
A tropical bacteria,
not a reptilian parasite.
I was sick as a dog,
but I wanted to make a good impression.
When we get back home,
I'll see to it you get some R&amp;R
in Norway or Canada...
someplace where there's not
a tropical bug in sight.
-Or reptiles.
Keep at it.
I'll get these to the bridge.
We've gotten close enough
to isolate their signatures.
The Insectoid ship is no longer with them.
Why would they leave the vortex?
We have no idea.
All we know is that the weapon
is being escorted
by a single Reptilian vessel... Dolim's.
At least we'll only have
one ship to contend with.
Here we go.
-Doctor?
-Fifteen minutes and counting.
Any sign of the sphere?
It's too soon.
Hold your course.
Degra's vessel is less than
20 minutes behind us.
Lieutenant, we're about
to drop into normal space.
Stand by to initiate the firing sequence.
We're ready.
Are you detecting any Earth vessels
near the coordinates?
No vessels,
but there is one small orbital station.
Unarmed.
Let me see Earth.
Enlarge.
It's a shame.
All that water.
The Aquatics would feel at home here.
I've got it.
How far?
20,000 kilometers.
Thirteen minutes left.
As soon as we make visual contact,
go to thrusters.
Set a heading
to latitude 15 degrees north.
-Deflector?
-Standing by.
They're 800,000 kilometers ahead.
Get your team ready to go.
Aye, sir.
Dolim's changing course.
They're heading for a space station.
Are we in visual range?
Yosemite Three?
A military installation?
A research post.
Usually 30 to 40 civilians aboard.
Hail them on this frequency.
( computer beeps )
The weapon's emitting disruption waves.
I can't get anything through.
Fifteen degrees north.
Drop to 2,000 meters.
Track starboard, 82 mark zero.
Aye.
Doc, there's something weird
happening to my skin.
-Me too!
-It was expected.
Try not to scratch it.
Eleven minutes remaining.
The guardians said
that once Earth is gone,
we're to destroy all human colonies.
I see no reason not to begin
with this station.
Target. Fire when ready.
They're heading back toward the weapon.
Ten degrees port.
Slow to 30 kph.
I'm transferring the target point
to the deflector array.
Got it.
Begin.
Fish in a barrel.
Less than 10 minutes to go.
( indistinct conversations )
( groans )
( rumbling )
What the hell's going on?
Power just fell 10%.
I'm picking up explosions on "E" deck.
Bridge to engineering. Report.
-( computer beeps )
-I'm losing the beam.
There are nine alien life-signs aboard.
They appear to be
trans-dimensional beings.
-How is that possible?
-This disturbance we're in,
it's obviously been altered
enough to sustain them.
Who's on Degra's ship?
Eight primates, three Arboreals...
and seven humans.
-Have their weapons been upgraded?
-No, sir.
Pathetic. Prepare to intercept.
They're arming their torpedoes.
Sir.
-How's Hoshi doing?
-She's holding up.
She and the Macos
are at the transporter device.
Remember, no heroics.
Just get us in
and then keep them off your ass.
( computer beeping )
There's another vessel
approaching at high warp.
They're asking for you.
You're not using your head, pink-skin.
That ship you're on
is no match for the Reptilian.
I'm busy, Shran. What are you doing here?
You should be impressed we managed
to track you through the vortex.
I anticipated that you'd need some help.
( all groan )
TUCKER: Corporal Kelly to the bridge.
Go ahead.
Our weapons are passing
right through them.
You got to stop this.
If I don't get full power back,
this is gonna take three, four minutes
longer than we thought.
We can't afford three or four minutes.
Corporal Kelly, listen to me very closely.
Modulate your weapons
to a rotating frequency
of 32.6 teracycles.
-Doctor?
-Our trans-dimensional friend,
the one we found in the pod...
I had quite a few hours
to study his physiology.
Let's hope my memory serves me well.
I'll be right in front of you, gentlemen.
Keep a low profile.
We're matching speed.
You said there were
no human vessels in the vicinity.
They're not human.
Destroy them both.
That third torpedo almost got you.
Be careful!
Prepare to come about to port.
Stay below me.
We'll need to get
within a kilometer of the weapon.
Just stay below me.
Let's fight back this time, shall we?
Bring the forward cannons online.
SHRAN: Go!
And tell Archer we're not even anymore.
He owes me!
( all groan )
It's coming back.
Tell them to keep doing
what they're doing.
-( beep )
-Walker to the bridge.
-Go ahead.
-We've secured engineering,
but I don't think
we've seen the last of them.
It's time for you to work your magic,
Mr. Tucker.
Within five minutes, everyone in this ship
is going to start dying.
No pressure.
OK, bring up the inversion sequence.
Start with the third one from the left.
Got it.
The second from the right.
( gasps )
Hoshi?
I'm all right!
The first one on the left is next.
Commander, sensors show the humans
are no longer aboard Degra's vessel.
These ships are drawing us away
from the weapon.
Get us back!
( rumbling )
-( computer beeps )
-What's going on?
Ignore it, Commander.
You've got less than two minutes.
Got it. Two to go.
( groans )
( screaming )
( groaning )
( gasps )
Hoshi?
( grunting )
( communicator beeps )
-Reed to Archer.
-Go ahead.
I'm pretty certain that was
the last of them, sir.
Good work. Now get back here.
-( computer beeping )
-T'Pol.
-T'Pol!
-All right!
Take us to full impulse.
Get us out of here.
Wait a minute. I'm almost there!
You don't have a minute, Commander!
Then give me 10 seconds.
I'm telling you, I've got it.
-( computer beeping )
-That's it! Time's up!
It sure is.
Now, Mr. Mayweather!
( choking )
( computer beeps )
The network is being destroyed.
Looks like we're getting out of this soup
faster than we thought.
Without the sphere,
their transformed space
must be collapsing in on itself.
Which one, Hoshi?
Number four, the fourth one from the left.
-Are you sure?
-Yes, yes.
Number five is the last one
after you disable the reactor.
But if we knock the reactor out,
won't that be enough?
We didn't come here
to disable this weapon.
We're here to destroy it.
Give me the charges.
I'll take care of it, sir.
I want the four of you
to get to the outer framework.
Beam back to Degra's ship.
As Chief Tactical Officer, sir--
This isn't open for debate, Lieutenant.
Don't worry, I'll be right behind you.
( beeping )
( alarm blaring )
Ugh!
What have you done?
( groans )
One Reptilian transported to the weapon.
Let's make sure
he has nowhere to go back to.
They have no shielding
on their starboard engines.
Target all weapons.
Can you get a lock on him?
Not yet.
Your captain is too deep
within the weapon.
( groaning )
( beeping )
T'POL: Acting Captain's starlog,
February 14, 2152.
We're holding position at the coordinates
where we were told to meet
Degra's vessel.
So far, there's been no word from them.
Long-range sensors are detecting
no evidence of the spheres.
TUCKER: None of them?
None.
And all the spatial anomalies
within our scanning range have vanished.
What about the thermobaric cloud barrier?
I can only detect a small section
from our present location,
but it appears to be dissipating.
Looks like we kept our end of the bargain.
It would appear that the Expanse
is returning to normal space.
We should've heard something by now.
What if they failed?
Earth could be--
Be patient.
( sighs )
And my skin's healing faster than yours.
I guess you Vulcans
aren't so tough after all.
Dr. Phlox says we should all
be back to normal
within two to three days.
I'm only kidding.
You look nice like this,
kind of like an old oil painting.
I am not old.
I will only be 66 years old
on my next birthday.
I can't believe you told me that.
You accused me of looking old.
That's not what I mean.
I've been trying to get you
to tell me your age
since we left spacedock.
Why now?
To Vulcans, certain information
is considered intimate.
Intimate? Hmm...
-( computer beeps )
-TRAVIS: Bridge to T'Pol.
Go ahead.
A vortex just opened. It's Degra's ship.
( static )
This is Enterprise. Please repeat.
-Captain, did you stop the weapon?
-( static )
Captain?
( computer beeps )
Set an intercept course.
It's done.
Done?
Captain Archer destroyed the weapon.
Where is he? Is he OK?
Captain didn't make it, Trip.
What do you mean, he didn't make it?
The weapon exploded
before he could transport to Degra's ship.
( computer beeps )
Come in.
Thank you.
The Aquatic vessel should
have you home in less than a day.
I was pleased to hear that
the Council has agreed to reconvene.
It was difficult for the Insectoids
to ignore recent events.
And the Reptilians?
They will join us eventually.
They have no choice but to accept
that the guardians' promises were empty.
Your captain's sacrifice
will not be forgotten.
Safe journey.
Thank you.
-( animals squeaking )
-It's all right.
It's all right.
It won't be much longer, I promise.
( sighs )
Is something wrong?
Oh, I think they sense
that we are traveling
in an unusual manner...
In the, uh, belly of the beast,
so to speak.
There are no windows here.
How would they know we're inside
the Aquatic vessel?
I don't have the slightest idea.
But I doubt I'll get much
peace and quiet around here
until we are flying under our own power.
It'll only be a few more hours.
Hmm...
Is there something I can do for you?
My skin hasn't fully healed yet.
Oh, you're doing fine.
Vulcans are obviously more sensitive
to the effects of mysterious realms.
I guess we're not so tough after all.
Excuse me?
Is there anything I'll need to treat this?
Only time.
How's morale?
It isn't easy for a crew
to lose its captain.
I suppose we'll all need time to heal.
Will he be all right?
Not for a while.
He lost his best friend.
But it's just a matter of time.
He'll be fine again.
Did you hear that?
The doctor says you'll be fine.
It's just a matter of time.
T'POL: Distance?
800,000 kilometers.
Set a course, Ensign.
You should be in your quarters.
With all due respect to Phlox,
I wouldn't miss this for the world.
Mind if we take a look?
Prettiest sight I ever saw.
It's all in one piece.
The Captain would be proud.
Open a channel to Starfleet headquarters.
( computer beeping )
Strange.
What?
They're not responding.
You'd think they'd be waiting
with bated breath.
Try another frequency.
I'm not picking up the orbital platforms.
The Reptilians destroyed Yosemite station.
It's not just Yosemite.
There's nothing coming from any of them.
I've rotated through all the frequencies.
Contact the Lunar One colony.
I already tried.
Prepare a shuttlepod.
I want you and Ensign Mayweather
to get down to San Francisco.
Find out what's wrong.
Looks pretty normal to me.
Then why the hell doesn't anyone
want to talk to us?
( sighs )
Land at the pad behind the command center.
Finally!
We've got three vessels approaching.
It's about time.
( computer beeps )
This is Commander Charles Tucker
of the starship Enterprise.
-You guys gave us quite a--
-( machine-gun fire )
What the hell?
Sir.
( conversations in German )