[ T'Pol ] Previously on "Enterprise"...
This species has technology
which allows them
To examine alternate time lines.
They've seen this future,
and they want to change the outcome.
[ Malcolm ]We've got less than 10 hours
before this weapon reaches earth.
The captain wants to take a team aboard
to destroy it.
[ Laser fire ]
[ Groaning ]
-Give me the charges.
-I'll take care of it, sir.
Don't worry. I'll be right behind you.
[ Malcolm ] Captain Archer
destroyed the weapon.
-Where is he? Is he okay?
-Captain didn't make it, Trip.
Prepare a shuttle pod.
I want you and Ensign Mayweather
to get down to San Francisco.
Find out what's wrong.
Sir.
[ Gunfire ]
This is commander Charles Tucker
of the starship Enterprise.
What the hell are you people doing?
Those are P-51s.
I've seen them at air shows.
I don't think this is an air show.
Are they breaking off?
Maybe we should follow them.
Try to find a landing port, set us down.
[ Explosion ]
Starboard injector.
Get us out of here.
[ Beeping ]
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And I will see my dream
come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna
change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart
will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength
of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend
or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got, I've got ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
[ Birds squawking ]
Rita Hayworth.
Veronica Lake.
Betty Grable.
[ Laughs ]
[ man ] Americans are good
at making movies.
They are not so good at fighting.
Someday, I will go to Hollywood
and I will meet Betty Grable.
Maybe you will introduce me, huh?
What do you think?
She's not your type.
[ Laughs ]
You know, in Hollywood movies,
Americans always win.
Too bad for you, you are not in a movie.
[ Explosion ]
Insurgents!
[ Gunfire ]
[ Speaking German ]
[ Groaning ]
Keep driving! Move! Move!
[ Groans ]
[ Gunfire continues ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gun cocks ]
[ Churchill ] As to the youth
of all the Britons, I say,
You cannot stop.
There is no halting place
at this point.
We have now reached
a point in the journey
Where there can be no pause.
We must go on.
It must be world anarchy
or world order.
[ Beeps ]
That was Winston Churchill.
I picked that up half an hour ago.
Well, it's true, then.
We're over 200 years
in the past.
I've also intercepted
several military dispatches
and their radio program,
something called "The Shadow."
We should run a complete diagnostic.
Start with the sensor array.
This isn't a damn sensor glitch.
We just pulled three .50-caliber bullets
From the shuttle pod hull.
And spare us the official Vulcan
position about time travel.
We are 200 years
in the past. Face it.
The first step to getting back
is ascertaining how we got here.
As soon as the diagnostic
is complete,
Run a scan for any anomalies
in the area.
Right away.
Maybe we're here for a reason.
Maybe this wasn't an accident.
For the moment,
we can't rule out any possibilities.
[ Grath ] The Germans believe
there are 5,000 resistance fighters
operating throughout the region.
They're becoming better organized,
Increasing their attacks.
We lost four men in the assault.
You should have chosen a safer route.
And you should have personally
overseen the transfer.
We were in the midst
of a crucial weapons test.
He was just an American prisoner.
He was more than that.
This communication
device he was carrying...
It's from the future.
A temporal agent?
Double the security details
At all the entrances to the compound.
If they have located us...
It won't be long before they strike.
How could they have possibly found us?
If the prisoner hadn't escaped,
We might know the answer to that question.
You know what I expect of you.
The prisoner will be recovered.
[ Door chimes ]
Come in.
You got a second?
I wanted to say, I was way out
of line earlier.
You have enough to worry about
Without me flying off the handle.
Your reaction was understandable.
I was just all set to get home.
I wasn't expecting to be in the middle
of another situation.
None of us were.
I was also looking forward to going home.
I thought perhaps
I would return to Vulcan.
It's been some time since I was there.
Sounds nice.
I was gonna lay on a different
beach every week for two months.
The only thing to figure out
Was whether to start in Tahiti
or in Cancun.
And the captain would always
try to put the best line
On the worst situation.
I wonder what he'd say to this one.
I think he'd be hard-pressed
to find any positive aspects.
But he would try, nevertheless.
[ Door chimes ]
Come in.
I've been going
over those military dispatches
That Hoshi picked up.
Some of them don't make sense.
They mention recent
battles in Virginia and Ohio.
There weren't any battles
fought there in World War II.
The Nazis never got to North America.
Something's very wrong down there.
It's chicken liver, your favorite,
with grated cheddar.
[ Sighs ]
No, I can't say I blame you.
I don't have much of an appetite myself.
Perhaps a Denobulan lullaby,
hmm, will improve your mood?
[ Whimpers ]
On the other hand, My singing would often
drive my children to tears.
Maybe what you'll need
is a nice thick steak.
I'll see what chef has on the menu.
Be right back.
[ Wheezing ]
[ Gasps ]
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, it's okay. It's all right.
I'm a friend.
Just cleaning you up a little.
War's a dirty business.
But you're lucky.
Bullet just missed the bone.
Where am I?
In my apartment... what's left of it.
I'm Alicia Travers.
Jonathan Archer.
Pleased to meet you.
What's the last thing you remember?
I was in a truck with a couple
of German soldiers.
There was an explosion.
Someone started shooting at us.
-I got away.
-You sure did.
And your S.S. Friends,
they're dead, which is how I like them.
You're my first bona fide P.O.W.
I usually fix up guys in the resistance.
Easy, easy, easy, easy, sailor.
You don't want to start bleeding again.
Sailor?
Yeah, that patch
on your shirt says "Enterprise."
You must have made it off before it sank.
How'd you wind up all the way over here?
I've been asking myself the same question.
[ Clears throat ]
What year is this?
It's 1944.
World War II.
I haven't heard it called that before,
But that's as good a description as any.
Used to be a pretty nice neighborhood,
even for coloreds.
As you can see, it's gone downhill.
[ Archer ] Where are we?
We in Brooklyn.
New York city?
[ Male ] The weapon fires
a modulating plasma pulse
Equivalent to the energy
produced by three 88mm shells.
Each pulse can destroy a tank.
[ Projector whirring ]
Very impressive.
When can we expect deployment?
I can't give you a specific timetable.
There are still some problems
to be addressed.
-Such as?
-Portability.
The weapons require considerable power.
In my century, there are energy cells
the size of a coin.
In this century...
It's somewhat more difficult.
What are these?
Requisition forms.
I require additional supplies.
"Eighty six metric tons
of aluminum plating.
A hundred and seventy
tons of carbon steel."
We can't keep diverting vital
materials from war production.
We are inside the home of the former
American President.
It seems to me your war effort
is going well enough.
That could change very quickly.
Intelligence suggests the Americans
are preparing a counter attack.
Our front lines are dangerously thin.
Supply routes are under constant
attack from resistance fighters.
A forceful enemy thrust could stand a good
chance of breaking through.
On top of this,
there'd been setbacks in Africa,
And the Russians are attempting
to retake Moscow.
While no one has expressed
this to the Fuhrer,
There is widespread belief that Germany
Has advanced too far too quickly.
All the more reason
to accede to my request.
The weapons I'm preparing
will make you immune
from any counterattack
anywhere in the world.
And I'm not just referring
to plasma rifles.
Imagine a plague...
Targeting non-Aryans.
No need for extermination camps.
Just a few grams of a pathogen
Introduced into the water supply.
You make promises.
All we ever see are films.
There is far too much
at stake for us to argue.
We have far too much in common.
We both embrace the ideals
of purity and perfection,
And we both face enemies
that would destroy us.
Now is not the time to end an association
That is vital to our mutual survival.
No one has proposed ending anything.
Then I'll expect delivery
by the end of the week.
[ Phlox ] Portions of Daniels' body
have aged at a dramatic rate.
In some areas,
the tissue is over 100 years old.
Yet other sections have been reduced
to an almost fetal stage.
Do you have any theories
as to what caused this?
It's not any kind of infectious organism,
at least, nothing that shows up
on my medical scanner.
Will he survive?
Frankly, with his amount
of cellular chaos,
I'm surprised he's still alive.
I doubt he'll live more than 24 hours.
He very well could be responsible
for our being here.
He could also be the only hope
of getting back to our own time.
It is imperative that I speak with him.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Groans ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Knock on door ]
Vic's been arrested.
-When?
-A few hours ago.
The Gestapo's clearing out
entire buildings,
Shooting people in the street.
They're looking for you.
The Germans are offering $10,000
for information leading to your capture.
-Why?
-Can't tell you.
Look, you son of a bitch,
My friend is probably
being tortured right now.
I want to know why.
It's classified.
I won't tell anyone.
-Sal.
-Shut up!
You got three seconds.
One...
Two, three.
Come on, Sal. Take it easy.
Take it easy. Come on, now. Easy. Easy.
All I can tell you
is we're on the same side.
Damn military.
You cut and run.
You leave us at the mercy
of these Nazi bastards.
I didn't cut and run.
Oh, yeah, yeah, I forgot.
It was an orderly retreat.
[ Siren wailing ]
Vic might break.
If he talks, it won't be safe here.
-We've been through this.
-Alicia.
This is my home. I'm not leaving.
We're gonna see if we can find out
any more information about vic.
He's conscious, but I don't know
for how long.
Where's Captain Archer?
Captain Archer is dead.
He was on the Xindi weapon
when it exploded.
Are you responsible
for sending us back in time?
Why?
The temporal cold war
has become an all-out conflict.
Temporal agents,
Dozens of them stationed
throughout the timeline.
They've been given orders
to change history.
For what purpose?
Each faction is trying to wipe
the others out.
It's a fight for dominance.
Daniels.
The events of this period
don't correspond with recorded history.
Germany has launched a successful invasion
of the United States.
Different incursions
are causing paradoxes.
Turbulence in the time stream.
I almost didn't make it back.
[ Gasping ]
How do we return to our century?
You can't.
It doesn't exist.
-Not the way you know it.
-Neither does mine.
It's all gone.
You have to stop him.
Stop who?
[ T'Pol ]Danie ls.
We're conducting extensive sweeps
Within a 15-mile radius of the ambush.
[ Ghrath ] We haven't found the prisoner,
But we have taken in several
members of the resistance.
They're being interrogated.
There's one that I suspect
took part in the ambush.
We're picking up scans
from a ship in orbit.
It's from the same time period
as the device we found
on the escaped prisoner.
This resistance member
you're interrogating...
Yes?
[ Beeping ]
Bring him to me.
Not bad.
Where's your husband now?
He's in the Pacific, on a destroyer.
I hear the war
isn't going any better over there.
Don't be expecting a second course.
It's not bad.
You're a rotten liar.
All the good stuff goes to the Germans.
I still can't believe it.
You know, that they're actually here.
I'll never forget the day
I saw that first German tank
Rolling up flat bush.
All the people streaming
across the Brooklyn bridge
Trying to get out of Manhattan.
The President on the radio,
vowing to persevere
right before the government
evacuated Washington.
[ Billie holiday's "my old flame"
plays on radio]
Right on time.
♪ My old flame ♪
Billie holiday.
Ah, good to know there's something
that you remember.
♪ Can't even think of his name ♪
♪ But its funny now and then ♪
♪ How my thoughts
Go flashing back again ♪
♪ To my old flame ♪
Germans outlawed colored music.
Some of the neighbors pass a phonograph
from house to house every night
so the Germans can't find it.
Just another way of telling them off.
♪ For I haven't met a gent
so magnificent ♪
Alicia.
I'm gonna ask you something.
It's gonna sound a little strange.
What else is new?
When I was in a German medical tent,
One of the soldiers
who came in to see me...
Wasn't like the other ones.
He had gray skin, red eyes.
He wasn't human.
This isn't the first time you've heard
something like this.
Sal mentioned some stories once,
but I didn't believe him.
They may be more than stories.
I need to track down this...
soldier I saw.
It's very important.
Would you contact Sal?
[ Tucker ] E.P.S. Conduit's fried.
Get to engineering
And pull a fresh one
out of the injector assembly.
Yes, commander.
Walsh?
[ Rattling ]
[ Beeping ]
[Silik ] Commander.
-Silik. Son of a bitch.
-Climb in.
-You brought us here.
-No.
Then who did?
What's happening is beyond
your comprehension.
Get in the shuttle pod.
I would rather not have
to discharge this weapon.
[ Grunts ]
[ Both grunting ]
[ Choking ]
[ Groans ]
[ Alarm beeping ]
Bay 1 is depressurizing.
Someone's launching a shuttlepod.
Hail them.
I'm picking up
one life-sign aboard. It's Suliban.
Phase cannons.
If this Nazi wasn't a human, what was he?
-I don't know.
-Just tell Sal I want to talk to him.
All right.
Here, it's hamburger.
Germans are cutting the meat ration again.
It's gonna be worth its weight in gold.
Thanks, Carmine.
Watch yourselves.
Used to be we'd get meat
on Wednesdays and Fridays.
Then it was just Wednesdays.
Nazis blame the resistance,
Say we're disrupting the food shipment.
Makes the Germans look like heroes.
-Yeah.
-Fighting to feed the people.
[ Speaks German ]
Look.
[ Sighs ]
No eye contact.
Why do you walk with her?
-Why not?
-Do you like Negroes?
-We don't want any trouble.
-Shut up, bitch.
Do we make you angry?
You could say that.
When we send her back to Africa,
you can go along.
You can run through the jungles together.
Like I said, neighborhood's gone downhill.
Before he lost consciousness,
Daniels told me there
was someone we had to stop.
At least now we know
who he was talking about.
Can you get a fix on the shuttlepod?
He disabled the transponder.
However, we are picking up trace
plasma signatures,
probably from the damage.
I think I can get us
Within three kilometers
of where it went down.
That will have to suffice.
Thing I can't understand,
why'd he go to the trouble
of saving my life?
[ Tucker ] He pulled me out of the launch
bay before he depressurized it.
Another item on our list
of "things to ponder."
Curfew starts in an hour.
-We got to move fast.
-[ Gunshot ]
Yeah, sometimes the Germans
don't wait for curfew.
[ Gunshots ]
Can't get used
to all this skulking around.
I know what you mean.
We used to own this neighborhood.
Yeah, well, tell him what you guys
did before the war.
Nothing to tell.
We were delegates for the construction
workers' union.
Right. The loan-sharking
was just a part-time job.
Hey, we helped people get out
of financial difficulty.
Since when is that a crime?
When they didn't pay you back on time.
That's where the crime part came in.
Come on, let's go.
[ Sal ] This guy's a welsher and a drunk.
I wouldn't put too much stock
Into what comes out of his mouth.
I'll keep that in mind.
I'm only doing this because Alicia asked.
Don't forget that.
What's this all about?
I want you to tell him what you
told me about your customer.
Who are you?
Just shut up and tell him.
I can't talk and shut up at the same time.
Talk.
The man comes to me for information.
Sometimes he asks about the resistance.
Sometimes he asks about the Gestapo.
He's keeping tabs on both sides.
Me? I don't know squat,
so I make stuff up.
-He pays good.
-What's he look like?
He always wears a hat.
Stays in the shadows.
I caught a glimpse of him once.
He ain't like nobody I ever seen,
that's for sure.
It's the red eyes I can't forget.
I want to talk to him.
-Forget it.
-That ain't part of the deal.
Sal.
What you owe me, take 20% off.
-Damn, Sal.
-What? I'm a generous guy.
-I don't know.
-Hey, you think the Germans are tough?
Get me in a bad mood.
[ Tucker ] Artillery.
[ Travis ] Hard to believe we're only
a few kilometers from New York city.
It's hard to believe this is earth.
[ Beeping ]
[ Tucker ] Plasma signature. That way.
[ Explosion ]
We're keeping the Germans busy,
more and more of us every day.
Irish gangs, dockworkers,
coloreds, even broads.
Some of these women,
they could shoot the fleas off a tick.
When the war's over, I got half of mine
I put them on the payroll.
[ Can rattling ]
Here. It's loaded.
Prazki?
You.
[Alicia ] Throw the gun down.
[ Carmine ] You're not following
directions. That's how people get hurt.
[ Archer ] You better take her advice.
[ Male ] What do you want?
Holy mother of...
[ Tucker] Tucker to Enterprise.
-T'pol.
-We found it.
No sign of Silik.
What's the shuttle pod's condition?
[ Tucker ] I'll need some more time
before I know if it will fly.
[ Sal ] You ever see anything
like that before?
-Maybe he's wearing some kind of mask.
-That's no mask.
[ Archer ] Who are you? Answer me.
I have nothing to say to you.
-How about if we pulled out your tongue?
-You're not what I expected.
Temporal agents are usually more informed.
-What the hell is a "temporal agent"?
-You wouldn't understand.
-Listen, you freak--
-Why are you changing history?
You're helping the Germans
win the war. Why?
-Because it suits us.
-How does this suit you?
Oh!
Sal, no! Damn it.
-It's better than he deserves.
-Get your hands off him!
-You want answers, don't you?
-[ Archer ] Not like that.
Just say the word, Sal.
I'll take him out right here.
The hell with it.
I don't know how long I can hold them off.
You better talk to me.
Now, who are you?
What are you doing here?
We're trapped. The Germans are helping
us construct a conduit
So we can find our way home.
You said I was a temporal agent.
We know you're from the future.
We detected your ship in orbit.
My ship.
It has the same markings
that were on your uniform.
I need to contact them.
Can I do it with this?
[ Siren wailing ]
We better get out of here.
The conduit, where is it being built?
You find it.
Come on. Come on.
You won't stop us.
When we get back,
you'll never have existed.
E.P.S. system's completely fused.
It could take a week.
I'm picking up movement in the area.
Looks like several vehicles.
-Commander.
-I heard.
Moving to plan "B."
What about Silik? We got to find him.
We will. One problem at a time.
[ Sal ] Geez, he looked like some
kind of demon.
[ Alicia ] His blood wasn't even red.
[ Carmine ] Was that my imagination,
Or did he say something about being
from the future?
He meant him.
[ Archer ] Archer to Enterprise.
You want any more of our help,
You're gonna tell us what's going on.
What was that back there?
That was an extraterrestrial.
A Martian?
I don't know what planet he was from.
-Where are you from?
-Upstate New York.
Fellas.
[ Clattering ]
A lot of people out past curfew.
-I don't like the looks of this.
-We got to get out of here.
-[ Door opens ]
-[ shouting in German ]
[ Nazi ] Move.
Sal!
Get out of here!
[ Groans ]
[ Whistle blows ]
[ Shouting in German ]
Enterprise, come in.
-Enterprise.
-What are you doing?
[ Machine-gun fire ]
Enterprise!
[ Groans ]
[ Gun clicking ]
Whoever you're calling,
they're not gonna get here in time.
Charges are set.
[ Dogs barking ]
[ Indistinct talking in German ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Shouting in German ]
[ Engine revs ]
[ Dogs barking ]
-It's done.
-I've lost them.
The explosion may have disrupted
their com signal.
-[ Beeping ]
-I'm picking up another signal.
-It's faint.
-Let's hear it.
Captain Archer to Enterprise.
Come in.
Enterprise, come in.
[ Beeps ]
Captain.
[ T'Pol ] Your transmission is very weak.
Do you read me?
T'pol, two to transport.
Leave your weapons on the ground
and stand up slowly.
We have a great deal to talk about.
It will have to wait.
You're all right.
You're on my ship.
How'd we get here?
It's kind of complicated.
Promise you won't do that again.
I promise.
Captain.
Welcome home.
We're not quite home yet,
but it's good to be back.
I guess I have some
catching up to do.
Status?
Several vehicles converged on the area
Moments before the shuttle pod exploded.
Keep searching.
This is one of the aliens' communicators.
Take it apart.
Figure out how to monitor
their transmissions.
[ Whimpering ]
It's nice to see you again, Captain.
I hope it's the last time
You'll have to look after Porthos.
It was a pleasure, as always.
-Is he awake?
-He doesn't have much time.
Jonathan.
Who are they?
The most dangerous faction
of the Cold War.
They're led by Vosk,
A fanatic violently opposed
to the temporal accords.
[ Gasping ]
Stay with me. Stay with me.
We almost captured him.
But he developed a form
of stealth time travel.
He escaped into the past.
We eventually located him,
but it was too late.
He returned to my century.
He and his people defeated us
And launched this war
that's destroying all of time.
I've sent you to this point
Because it's here
that Vosk can be stopped.
If you succeed, the war will never happen.
The timeline will be restored.
[ Wheezing ]
One of his people told me
they were building a conduit.
Vosk's time-travel device had a drawback.
It was a one-way trip.
He needed to construct
the conduit to get home.
But he was forced to use technology
From this time period.
The machine would have to be enormous.
Find it. Destroy it.
He must not succeed. Stop him.
[ Gasping ]
[ Flat line ]
Your colleague has managed to evade us.
I assure you, whatever I want to know,
You will tell me... Gratefully.
Are we supervising another test?
Notify me when they're ready
for questioning.