[ Archer ]Previously on "Enterprise"...
We just pulled three .50-caliber bullets
From the shuttlepod hull.
We are 200 years in the past.
[ Nazi ] Insurgents!
[ Gunshots ]
Ugh!
Your colleague has managed to evade us.
I assure you, whatever I want to know,
you'll tell me.
[ Archer ] Where are we?
We in Brooklyn.
The weapons I'm preparing
will make you immune
From any counterattack,
anywhere in the world.
The Germans are offering $10,000
for information leading
to your capture. Why?
All I can tell you
is we're on the same side.
Holy mother of...
We're trapped.
The Germans are helping us
construct a conduit
So we can find our way home.
I've sent you to this point
Because it's here that Vosk
can be stopped.
If you succeed,
the timeline will be restored.
One of his people told me
they were building a conduit.
[ Daniels ] Find it, destroy it.
[ Gasping ] he must not succeed.
Stop him.
[ Archer ] And now, the conclusion.
[ Announcer ] "News on parade."
America and Germany together
in the fight for freedom!
In his first visit to the home
of the brave,
the German chancellor
Received a warm welcome
from the big apple!
[ Crowd cheering ]
He greeted enthusiastic crowds
in Times Square
And took in the view
From the top of the Empire State building.
Watch that first step!
Later, the fuhrer paid a call
to Lady Liberty,
where he was given the keys to the city.
The whirlwind tour was capped off
By a four-hour speech to city leaders
Where the fuhrer outlined his vision
For a prosperous alliance
between Germany and America.
Vowing to root out the parasitic elements
that have crippled our economy since 1929
And to liberate the masses
From the grip of financial profiteers.
Together, we will put Americans
back to work!
Two great nations,
marching side by side
toward a bold future!
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And I will see my dream
come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna
change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart
will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength
of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend
or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got, I've got ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
Our intelligence sources are convinced
That the American counterattack
Will be launched within days.
It's no longer a rumor, it's fact.
I assume you're taking
the necessary steps.
-[ Voks ] What is that?
-An intelligence briefing.
According to this, your squadron performed
Flawlessly in recent field tests.
You've been spying on us.
We're protecting our interests.
I suppose I would have done the same.
Tell your fuhrer
he'll receive the squadron
When I deem it ready for deployment.
This says it is ready for deployment.
With all due respect,
your intelligence is flawed.
We are tired of your stalling!
And I am tired of your threats.
You and your men have taken an oath
to defend Germany.
We take that oath seriously.
Do you?
You've made certain promises
to me as well.
We've provided everything
you've asked for.
You'll not receive a single truckload
Of additional supplies
Till you fulfill your part
of the agreement.
General, you might consider
what would happen
If my weapons were to fall
into the hands of the allies.
Imagine Berlin...
Obliterated by plasma cannons.
I should have you arrested for treason.
You are a fool.
You think we're equals because I allow you
to participate in this struggle.
You fight to control nations.
We dominate entire worlds.
We extend our will across time.
If your race were to endure
for a million years,
you couldn't begin to approach
what we've accomplished.
The next time you feel the urge
to threaten me,
remember this...
I can erase you from history,
as if you never existed.
She was around my age.
Twenty six.
[ Sighs ]
Ensign O'malley.
How'd she die?
In a battle with a hostile species.
There's still war in the future?
On earth, between human beings,
war's been eliminated.
But the galaxy's a big place,
with thousands of species.
Not all of them have the same
values we have.
Spaceships.
People from other planets.
People from the future.
It's all a little too much
For Alicia Travers from Bensonhurst.
besides, I'm afraid of heights.
I can send you anywhere in the world.
To a place that isn't occupied
by the Germans.
Seem to be fewer and fewer
of those places every day.
I want to go home.
To my neighborhood.
There are a lot of people
in trouble down there
And I'm not gonna
just turn my back on them.
But you knew I was going
to say that, didn't you?
I had a feeling.
Two of my men are missing.
They could be hiding out,
they might have been taken prisoner.
They could be dead.
We've got eyes on--on every street corner.
I can--I can put a word out.
Archer...
With this ship, with all this power,
You could help us.
You can help us stop those bastards.
-I know.
-Then do it.
Start with Berlin.
Wipe that damn place off the map,
And don't stop until you kill every last
one of them, because what they--
We're going to stop them.
That's one of the reasons we're here.
But we're going to do it another way.
Okay.
I guess you know what you're doing.
You gonna start by sending me down
With that dissolver thing, huh?
Shuttle pods are damaged.
The transporter is all we have.
Archer, you promised me
I wouldn't have to go through that again.
I'm gonna have to break that promise.
Okay. How does that thing work, anyway?
[ Chuckles ]
On second thought, I-I'd rather not know.
Right away.
Begin the test sequence.
Based on the interrogations,
I believe the prisoners
are not temporal agents.
I've arrived at the same conclusion.
Their technology suggests
They're from a period too early
for time travel.
They don't even seem to know
how they got to this century.
It's curious.
Still, I refuse to believe their presence
here is an accident.
[ Beeping ]
There's a surge in one
of the power modules.
Run a complete system scan.
Isolate the fault.
[ Beeping ]
Our time is running out.
The Germans are becoming impatient.
Why not give them what they want?
I don't trust these people, I never have.
I'm not about to furnish them with weapons
That could be used against us.
Return the prisoners
to their holding cell.
See that they get medical attention.
Go.
[ Grunts ]
Bring the doctor immediately.
[ guard ] Jawohl.
[ Sighs ]
[ Groans ]
[ Door closes, locks ]
I think I've pinpointed
where the timeline changed.
Someone assassinated Lenin in 1916.
-Who took his place?
-No one.
So, without Lenin, the Bolsheviks
never gained power.
Russia didn't become communist,
And Germany never considered it a threat.
Hitler was able to concentrate
on the west.
Yeah. After France, Belgium
and the Netherlands fell,
Hitler quickly took England,
And then the Eastern United States.
But Vosk and his men arrived
on earth recently.
A few years ago.
Then they couldn't have been responsible
for the changes that took place in 1916.
The police never captured
Lenin's assassin.
Some bystanders claimed that the killer
vanished into thin air.
Daniels said that different factions
In the temporal war are changing history
Throughout the timeline.
Maybe this assassin was working
for one of them.
But I thought we were here
to prevent Vosk
from starting the temporal war.
Chicken or the egg.
[ Communicator beeps ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
Go ahead.
I'm receiving a transmission. It's Vosk.
[ Door opens ]
This is Captain Archer.
Your voice sounds familiar, Captain.
Have we met?
What do you want?
I believe I have two of your men.
-Are they all right?
-I think it would be mutually beneficial
to discuss this face-to-face.
We can bring you aboard.
I was thinking of a more neutral location.
There's a remote area outside the city.
That's not what I'd consider neutral.
You have scanners.
Examine the area before coming down.
I'll have three men with me
and your crewmen.
A few hours ago, you tried to kill me.
The situation has changed.
I'm sending you the coordinates.
If you're interested, meet me in one hour.
[ Beeping ]
Got them.
[ Truck approaching ]
[ Brakes squeal ]
It's good to see you again, Captain.
Where are my men?
[ Bolt rattling ]
Captain!
I don't believe it.
How can--
Are you all right?
We weren't exactly treated like royalty.
I apologize
For the aggressiveness of our questioning.
Aggressive?
We were operating
under a false impression.
We're okay.
-Get back to the ship.
-Wait a minute. You're coming with us.
Trip.
[ Communicator beeps ]
Beam them up.
You have your men, Captain.
Now, it's your turn to reciprocate.
How?
I wish to discuss something with you.
Go on.
A species with your level of technology
Doesn't possess the capability
for time travel.
We had a little help.
As I suspected.
What do you know about me?
I know that you're trapped here
And that you're trying
to get back to the 29th century.
I also know you've made a deal
with the Germans.
They're giving you supplies,
helping you build a time machine.
I see I was both right
and wrong about you.
You're not a temporal agent.
But you're here to do their bidding.
If you carry out your mission,
If you make it back to the 29th century,
You'll ignite a war that will devastate
the timeline.
You've only heard one side
of the story, Captain.
The temporal agents who sent you
here are a tyrannical sect,
Imposing their will on countless
cultures throughout history.
They enforce the temporal accords,
preserve the timeline.
They manipulate the timeline
to serve their own needs.
If you've ever dealt with them,
then you know they do much more
Than watch history unfold.
They interfere with events.
They have an agenda.
So do you.
At least I don't hide my intentions.
[ Vosk ] It's true, I don't agree
with the temporal accords.
I believe that time travel is a technology
No different than your warp drive
To be utilized for the benefit
of all species.
Societies, cultures
can be improved through...
Careful manipulation of historical events.
Who decides what improvements are needed?
I won't be drawn
into a philosophical discussion.
There's one simple reason
why you should help me, Captain.
And what's that?
I can send you back to your century.
History's been changed.
The century
I left will be completely different.
Once I've defeated the temporal agents,
I'll reverse the damage done
to your timeline.
Your history will return
to the way it was.
I'm severely limited by 20th-century
earth technology.
The resources aboard your ship
Will greatly accelerate my task.
Go back, reunite with your crewmen,
And consider what I have said.
[ Archer ] How are they doing?
Oh, a few cuts and bruises.
What happened after we beamed up?
You, uh, make some kind of deal?
-He thinks we're considering it.
-Are we?
Uh, Captain.
What'd you see down there?
We were in some
huge building, like a factory.
They're constructing something big.
The Germans are helping them.
I overheard them talking.
They mentioned something
about a temporal conduit.
I know it sounds crazy,
but I think it's a time machine.
Daniels sent us here
to stop them from completing it.
Problem is...
It's protected by some kind of...
Energy shield.
[ Both grunting ]
Ugh!
Who dressed this?
Nicky Giorgo.
Oh.
What do you want? He's a mechanic.
He should stick to cars.
[ Sighs ]
At least it doesn't look infected.
Could have been worse.
I could've ended up like Sal.
It's a miracle you got away.
Guess you should know.
What's that supposed to mean?
[ Gasps ]
I know.
I heard a rumor.
When the soldiers cornered you and Archer,
You two disappeared into thin air,
like ghosts.
That's crazy.
That's what I said.
But then again,
I didn't believe in Nazi Martians,
You know, not until I saw one myself.
Want to tell me what this is?
You went through my jacket?
-I was looking for a cigarette.
-What is it?
It's a radio.
I never seen a radio like this.
It looks like that thing Archer
took off that Martian guy,
Or whatever he was.
Archer gave this to me
so that I could talk to him.
Talk to him? Where is he?
Alicia, you been like
a little sister to us.
You gonna start keeping secrets now?
[ Beeps ]
Where's my engineer?
Silik.
This disc you are carrying.
It contains schematics of Vosk's facility.
This is what you came here for, isn't it?
You persist in asking questions
You know I will not answer.
I'll try answering them myself, then.
Your benefactor wants to do more
Than just project his image into the past.
He wants the technology
to travel into the past.
Somehow, he found out
That Daniels was sending Enterprise here.
So you were ordered to hitch a ride.
Your mission was to break
into Vosk's compound
And steal this.
[ Chuckles ]
Tell me, how was I planning
to send that to the future?
Maybe that's why you came back aboard.
Maybe you need Enterprise.
An impressive display, Captain.
I'm glad you're not disappointed.
Though I'm not implying you're correct
in any of your assumptions.
Of course not.
But you don't have the answer
you're seeking.
The whereabouts of your missing crewman.
I think you left him somewhere
inside Vosk's compound.
And for your sake, he'd better be alive.
You've changed, Captain.
And not at all for the better.
[ Indistinct conversation ]
A large amount of data has been stolen
From our computer system, Captain.
We found trace amounts of bioresidue.
The thief is from your time period.
He's Suliban.
He's aboard my ship.
He's a stowaway.
We've encountered his faction before.
I want to speak with him.
I can't allow that.
And I suppose you aren't examining
The technology he stole from us?
I reserve that right.
And I reserve the right to destroy you.
I have a plasma cannon aimed
at your ship, Captain.
And I have phase cannons aimed
at your facility.
I want an answer to my proposal.
The answer is no.
[ Beeping ]
[ Alarm blaring ]
Return fire.
Their shields are still holding.
Travis.
They're moving out of range.
We needed them.
We'll complete our objective
with the resources at hand.
Resume your work.
Engines took a serious hit.
Weapons are down.
Get to work on repairs.
Keep looking over those schematics.
Find a way to disable the shields
Protecting that compound.
I'm getting my crewman back.
You're gonna help me get inside
the facility.
And then?
Are you going to destroy it?
Yes.
I don't care about your crewman, Captain.
But I don't want Vosk to succeed
any more than you do.
I'll help you.
There is one problem.
I used my genetic enhancements
to get inside the building.
Your presence will negate that advantage.
We'll work around it.
You should be able to deactivate
the shields from this console.
Here's the procedure.
The data from the disk
was extremely helpful.
You're welcome.
When the shields are down,
give us 10 minutes,
Then destroy the facility.
Our targeting array is off line.
We're in need
of Commander Tucker's skills.
Do what you can.
Move in close and fire
point-blank if you have to.
Understood.
Good luck.
Three American divisions
have crossed the Ohio river.
Two more are advancing
from the South toward Washington.
By direct order from the Fuhrer,
The squadron
is to be transferred immediately
to Luftwaffe regional command.
I am to personally oversee the deployment.
Weapons of this complexity
require extensive training to operate.
We'll discuss the particulars
Once you've fulfilled your obligation.
Six hours.
Why the delay?
The planes must be readied for transport.
Six hours.
We're leaving tonight.
Begin preparations.
Each time we open a conduit,
it collapses within seconds.
Human leaders often speak of destiny.
The conduit will hold.
[ Glass shatters ]
How do I look? Better?
[ Gunshots ]
From my dealings with you and your crew,
I'd come to believe that your race
Was inherently unaggressive.
[ Beeping ]
[ Archer ] We've come a long way
in a short time.
[ Silik ] One thing is clear.
When necessary,
humans are fully capable
of reverting to old methods.
The way you handled the Xindi threat
was extremely effective.
No doubt it's the reason why Daniels
chose you to stop Vosk.
[ Vehicle approaching ]
Speaking of Vosk,
it seems to me
That you both have
a common enemy...Daniels.
Why haven't you decided
to work together?
[ Silik ] One doesn't join forces
with Vosk.
-He's found some partners here.
-They're only a means to an end.
To him and his followers,
Other species exist only
to serve their needs.
[ Archer ] Sounds like you and Vosk
have some history.
[ Silik ] His faction once tried
to eradicate the Suliban.
They traveled into our past,
Altered it to prevent our species
From attaining sentience.
Then how is it that you're here?
He was stopped by the temporal agents.
Are you saying you
owe Daniels' people your lives?
They still oppose us.
They're still our enemy.
That will never change.
[ Indistinct conversation ]
[ man ] What the hell you want?
[ Archer ] I'm looking for Alicia Travers.
Who's asking?
My name's Archer.
[ Carmine ] Still huntin' Martians?
[ Alicia ] You just missed Billie Holiday.
[ Carmine ] What are we going
after this time?
The lochness monster?
[ Beeping ]
I'm picking up a surge of radio chatter,
orders coming in German and English.
There's heavy bombing,
most of it in eastern Pennsylvania
And Southern Virginia.
[ Malcolm ] Could be an allied attack.
Could it pose a danger to the Captain?
The closest fighting
is 100 kilometers south of New York city.
Incredible.
What's our repair status?
Engines are at 36%.
Maneuvering thrusters are off line.
Weapons?
The targeting array's fried.
We'll be shooting in the dark.
What's so important about this facility?
They're building weapons there,
extremely powerful weapons.
What I hear,
You have some pretty powerful
weapons yourself.
I made her tell me everything.
Not that I believe all of it.
Do we really need these people?
What do you mean, "these people"?
I don't see how
they can be of any use to us.
I'll tell you how I could
be of use to you.
How about I start removing
your teeth with my knuckles?
-All right.
-Are you threatening me?
-Hey, give the man a prize!
-Why would you do that?
I'm gonna kill this guy!
Hey, Carmine.
Archer, what do you want us to do?
Hey, I haven't signed off on this yet.
Sal went along with you,
and look what it got him.
If I'm gonna lose any more people,
it better be a good reason.
Look, you know what, Carmine?
I'm gonna make this real easy for you.
I'm gonna help him.
All you have to do is decide
whether or not you're gonna help me.
Our greatest scientist once said,
"Every moment we live,
we are moving through time.
We've earned the right
to choose which direction."
The mastery of time has allowed
us to perfect ourselves,
To reach our full potential as a people,
And to vanquish those who oppose us.
There's just one last enemy to deal with.
Soon... History will belong to us.
We will stretch out our hands
and mold it according to our will.
Not even the gods of our ancestors
could have imagined such power.
My brothers...
We are going home.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Tires screeching ]
[ Soldiers shouting ]
[ Gunfire ]
What a way to spend a Saturday night!
[ Screaming ]
Ah!
It only opens from the inside.
[ Shouting indistinctly ]
There's too many of them! Come on!
[ Tires screeching ]
-Oh, it's nice to see you.
-Yeah.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Insurgents. We don't know how many.
A fortuitous development.
Let the Germans deal with them,
Continue with the preparations.
[ Indistinct conversation ]
[ Communicator beeps ]
We're in.
Making our way to the console.
[ T'Pol ] Our targeting array
is still down.
We're going to have to drop out
of orbit to get close enough.
Understood.
Have you located Commander Tucker?
Not yet.
It's second on my list, believe me.
[ Beeping ]
[ Archer ] Take cover.
They seem to be 4% lower than before.
[ Thudding ]
They're activating the conduit.
Work fast, Captain.
[ Alarm blaring ]
-He did it.
-Take us in.
Aye.
[ Alarm blaring ]
[ Groans ]
[ Gunfire ]
We're in an extremely precarious position.
[ Archer ] I hadn't noticed.
It might help if I had a weapon.
Sorry, only one to go around.
Silik!
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasping ]
The earth ship has entered the atmosphere.
Activate the plasma weapon.
We can't spare the power.
Then deploy the squadron.
Destroy them.
No!
The squadron is going to the front.
Execute my order.
I am taking command of this facility.
You are relieved.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Gunshots ]
I'm sorry, General.
But I'm afraid I have to end our alliance.
[ Gunshot ]
-Archer to Enterprise.
-[ Gasping ]
Archer to Enterprise!
They're in the atmosphere.
Ionization.
The signal can't penetrate.
We'll get you out of here.
I think not. [ Gasps ]
You've proven a worthy opponent, Captain.
I would have preferred
to die fighting you.
[ Gasps ]
But I suppose I can settle for this.
-Trip.
-Hold it right there.
-Trip, it's me.
-Shut up.
Drop the disguise, Silik,
or I'll blow your ugly head off.
If you do, you'll probably regret it.
Captain?
Good to see you, Commander.
You're alive?
As long as you don't pull that trigger.
[ Chuckles ]
I can't--I can't believe it.
The building's about to blow up.
-Gotcha.
-This way.
Distance?
One hundred kilometers.
Targeting scanners still can't get a lock.
I'm gonna have to do this
the old-fashioned way.
Switching to visual scanners.
Slow us down. 200 kph.
A group of aircraft are taking off
from a base north of Manhattan.
They're headed towards us.
Nicky, cover them!
You got to pull your people out.
Oh, I'm having too much fun.
In a few seconds, this entire
area's gonna be bombed.
Planes?
Start falling back!
We got to get the hell out of here!
Hey. Guess we have to say goodbye
all over again.
It's harder the second time.
Can't argue with that.
I want my neighborhood back...
The way it was.
And my husband, I want him home.
Fix all that, okay?
I'll try.
[ Sighs ]
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
Hey.
You're welcome.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Plane engines roaring ]
German dive bombers... stukas.
Nothing too much to worry about.
However, they were fitted with sirens
to frighten the enemy during an attack.
They fire 7.9-millimeter rounds.
Mr. Reed.
We're too far away.
I still can't see it.
[ Alarm blaring ]
It appears that bullets
and sirens aren't all they have.
Photonic torpedoes.
It's holding!
I'm reading a powerful energy
surge inside the facility.
-Malcolm.
-One more kilometer.
Destiny.
I can see it.
Take it out.
No!
[ Daniels ] It's quite a sight.
The time line's resetting itself.
You did it. Vosk is dead.
He didn't make it back.
All of the damage he caused,
it never happened.
And you're here to give me
a pat on the back.
-In a way.
-Well, I don't want it.
I want you to leave me
and my crew alone.
We're done with you and your damned
temporal cold war.
It's coming to an end
because of what you did.
You have no idea how many lives
you've saved.
I'll take your word for it.
Just send us home.
It's almost ready.
Goodbye, Jonathan.
Captain.
It's been a privilege.
Everyone all right?
Captain.
We're in the right place.
Let's find out if we're in the right time.
Hoshi?
[ Beeping ]
Multiple signals.
Lunar one colony, orbital platforms,
San Francisco, they're all calling in.
[ Beeping ]
I'm picking up vessels approaching,
dozens of them.
Do they look friendly?