[ APPLAUSE ]
WELL DONE, JONATHAN.
THANK YOU, ADMIRAL.
[ PEOPLE WHISTLING ]
[ SIGHS ]
I'VE BEEN TOLD THAT PEOPLE
ARE CALLING US HEROES.
WHEN IT COMES TO MY CREW...
YOU WON'T GET
ANY ARGUMENT FROM ME.
[ APPLAUSE ]
BUT I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT...
THAT WE REMEMBER...
THE HEROES
WHO AREN'T WITH US.
THE 27 CREWMEN
WHO DIDN'T MAKE IT BACK.
WITHOUT THEIR SACRIFICE,
I WOULDN'T BE STANDING HERE
RIGHT NOW.
NONE OF US WOULD.
BUT I'M SURE I SPEAK
ON BEHALF OF MY ENTIRE CREW
WHEN I SAY...
IT'S GOOD TO BE HOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
EXCUSE ME.
SCOTCH.
THE BAR'S RESERVED
FOR REGULAR CUSTOMERS.
GALACTIC HEROES
HAVE TO SIT AT A TABLE.
I HEARD ABOUT YOUR PROMOTION.
CONGRATULATIONS, CAPTAIN.
THANKS.
CHEERS.
SO, WHAT WAS IT LIKE
IN THE EXPANSE?
YOU'LL BE AT THE DEBRIEFING
TOMORROW, WON'T YOU?
MM-HMM.
I WOULDN'T WANT
TO SPOIL ANY SURPRISES.
BESIDES, I'VE GOT
MORE IMPORTANT QUESTIONS.
SEEN ANY GOOD MOVIES
WHILE I WAS GONE?
ANOTHER WORLD WAR III EPIC.
[ CHUCKLES ]
IT SWEPT ALL THE AWARDS.
BUT YOU HAVEN'T MISSED MUCH.
EARTH'S BEEN HOLDING ITS BREATH
FOR THE PAST YEAR
WONDERING IF THE XINDI
WERE GONNA COME BACK
AND FINISH THE JOB.
ON THE BRIGHT SIDE,
THERE'VE BEEN MORE WEDDINGS
AND BIRTHS THAN EVER BEFORE.
I DON'T SEE A RING.
I'M MARRIED TO STARFLEET...
JUST LIKE YOU.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE TAKING ENOUGH CLOTHES
TO LAST A YEAR.
YOU WANTED SOMETHING?
I TOLD THE CAPTAIN
I WANTED TO STAY ABOARD
AND SUPERVISE THE REFIT,
BUT HE SUGGESTED
I TAKE A BREAK.
MORE LIKE AN ORDER, ACTUALLY.
PROBLEM IS,
I'M NOT SURE WHERE TO GO.
LIZZIE'S GONE. MY HOMETOWN
DOESN'T EXIST ANYMORE.
[ SIGHS ]
GUESS THIS IS MY HOME NOW.
YOU COULD COME WITH ME.
TO VULCAN?
THE TRANSPORT LEAVES
AT 1100 HOURS.
WHERE WOULD I STAY?
THERE'S A GUEST ROOM
IN MY MOTHER'S HOME.
OH, YOUR MOM'S HOUSE, HUH?
WHAT, UH --
WHAT DOES SHE KNOW ABOUT ME?
MM. ABOUT US?
I'VE NEVER MENTIONED YOU.
SO, YOU'D INTRODUCE ME AS...
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER III.
YOU'VE TOLD THE CAPTAIN
THAT YOU DON'T GET TO SEE
AS MANY ALIEN CULTURES
AS YOU'D LIKE.
YOU'VE NEVER BEEN TO VULCAN.
1100 HOURS, HUH?
I'D BETTER START PACKING.
WE'VE TIED
THESE STATIONS DIRECTLY
INTO THE PRIMARY
E.P.S. JUNCTION.
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND IF I STEAL
SOME OF THESE IMPROVEMENTS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I WON'T SAY ANYTHING,
IF YOU DO ME A SMALL FAVOR.
MY SENIOR OFFICER CANDIDATES.
I'D LIKE TO GET YOUR OPINION.
YOU'VE SERVED
WITH A FEW OF THEM.
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO TALK TO SOMEONE
ABOUT INSTALLING
A LUMBAR SUPPORT.
YOU'RE GONNA SPEND
A LOT OF HOURS IN THAT CHAIR.
WE'VE IMPROVED
HULL POLARIZATION BY 12%.
WE'LL BE ABLE TO HANG IN A
FIRE-FIGHT A LITTLE LONGER.
VENTRAL AND DORSAL
TORPEDO LAUNCHERS,
PULSED PHASE CANNONS.
UPGRADES YOU RECOMMENDED.
WHAT IS IT?
I HAD AN ARGUMENT ONCE
WITH CAPTAIN JEFFERIES.
HE WAS ONE OF THE DESIGNERS
OF THE N.X.-CLASS.
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
I TOLD HIM I DIDN'T WANT TO BE
IN COMMAND OF A WARSHIP
TRYING TO MAKE FIRST CONTACT
WITH NEW SPECIES.
[ CHUCKLES ]
JEFFERIES WAS RIGHT.
WE NEEDED THOSE WEAPONS
AND A HELL OF A LOT MORE.
THE ASTEROIDS WERE LOADED
WITH TRELLIUM ORE.
WE THINK THE VULCANS ENTERED
THE FIELD IN ORDER TO MINE IT.
TRELLIUM?
IT'S AN ALLOY THAT PROTECTS
AGAINST SPATIAL ANOMALIES.
SHIPS IN THE EXPANSE USED IT
TO INSULATE THEIR HULLS.
YOUR LOG REFLECTS THAT
WHEN YOU BOARDED THE SELEYA,
THAT YOU FOUND THE CREW IN
A "DELUSIONAL, VIOLENT STATE."
THEY ATTACKED US
THE MINUTE WE DOCKED.
THE TRELLIUM HAD A TOXIC EFFECT
ON THE VULCANS,
DAMAGED THEIR NEURAL PATHWAYS.
THEY LOST THE ABILITY
TO SUPPRESS THEIR EMOTIONS.
ACCORDING TO YOUR LOG,
THE ENTIRE CREW OF THE SELEYA
WAS KILLED
WHEN YOU TRIGGERED
A REACTOR BREACH.
YEAH,
THE BREACH WAS AN ACCIDENT.
WE WERE TRYING
TO DISABLE THEIR POWER GRID.
UH, AS FAR AS
I CAN DETERMINE,
YOU DIDN'T TRY TO SAVE
A SINGLE VULCAN CREWMAN.
THERE WAS NO POINT.
THEY WERE TOO FAR GONE.
IS THAT YOUR
MEDICAL OPINION, CAPTAIN?
PHLOX MADE THAT DETERMINATION.
OUR SPECIALISTS HAVE EXAMINED
THE DATA YOU SENT BACK.
IT'S FAR FROM CERTAIN
THAT THE NEUROLOGICAL DAMAGE
WAS IRREVERSIBLE.
THERE WAS NOTHING
WE COULD DO FOR THEM.
T'POL WAS EXPOSED
TO THE TRELLIUM.
SHE RECOVERED.
I COULDN'T HELP THEM.
THERE'S NO NEED
TO GET EMOTIONAL, CAPTAIN.
YOU SPENT SEVERAL HOURS IN THE
SHIP'S AUXILIARY CONTROL ROOM.
IN THAT TIME, DID YOU TRY
TO ACCESS THE INTERNAL SENSORS
OR DOWNLOAD
THE COMPUTER DATABASE?
-NO.
-SO, IN EFFECT,
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT REALLY
HAPPENED ABOARD THE SELEYA.
WHAT THE HELL DOES THAT MEAN?
BECAUSE OF THIS OVERSIGHT,
WE'LL NEVER HAVE A COMPLETE
PICTURE OF THE EVENTS
THAT LED TO
THE SHIP'S DESTRUCTION.
I JUST TOLD YOU EXACTLY WHAT LED
TO THE SHIP'S DESTRUCTION.
CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT GONNA SIT HERE
AND BE ACCUSED
OF MURDERING THOSE PEOPLE.
NO ONE IS ACCUSING YOU
OF ANYTHING, CAPTAIN.
MAYBE THAT CREW
WOULD STILL BE ALIVE
IF YOU'D BEEN
A LITTLE MORE HELPFUL.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
YOU DID EVERYTHING YOU COULD
TO SABOTAGE OUR MISSION.
I GOT MORE HELP
FROM THE ANDORIANS
THAN I EVER GOT
FROM THE HIGH COMMAND!
THAT'S ENOUGH, CAPTAIN.
THIS PLANET WOULD BE
A CLOUD OF DUST RIGHT NOW
IF WE'D LISTENED TO YOU!
THAT'S ENOUGH!
HOW CAN YOU BE
TAKING HIS SIDE?
I AM NOT
TAKING ANYONE'S SIDE.
YOU WERE OUT OF LINE.
THEY DON'T LIFT A FINGER
TO HELP US,
AND NOW I HAVE TO JUSTIFY MYSELF
TO THAT SON OF A BITCH?
THE DEBRIEFING'S ON HOLD
INDEFINITELY.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE SOME TIME OFF
TO CLEAR YOUR HEAD.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, ADMIRAL,
I DON'T NEED A VACATION.
THAT'S AN ORDER, CAPTAIN!
LIEUTENANT, UM,
IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND.
[ SIGHS ]
UH...
NOT EXACTLY
TRAVELING LIGHT, ARE YOU?
[ CHUCKLING ]
THANK YOU.
WHY LEAVE
THE COMFORTS OF HOME,
WHEN YOU CAN
TAKE IT ALL WITH YOU, HMM?
OKAY.
[ SIGHS ]
I TRUST YOU'LL BE TAKING
THE PROPER PRECAUTIONS
ON THE SURFACE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, I'M SURPRISED
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD.
AN ANDORIAN AND TWO RIGELIANS
WERE ATTACKED.
ATTACKED? WHY?
WELL, APPARENTLY,
THE XINDI INCIDENT
HAS CAUSED
A DEGREE OF XENOPHOBIA.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
IN THIS DAY AND AGE.
I'M TOLD THE VULCANS
ARE STAYING BEHIND
THE WALLS OF THEIR COMPOUND.
WELL, I'M NOT GOING TO
LET A FEW ISOLATED INCIDENTS
DISRUPT MY VACATION PLANS,
HMM?
[ GRUNTING ]
I LIVED ON EARTH
FOR MANY YEARS
BEFORE COMING ABOARD ENTERPRISE.
I DON'T THINK THIS IS THE SAME
PLANET YOU REMEMBER, DOCTOR.
PEOPLE ARE LOOKING
FOR SOMEONE TO BLAME,
AND THEY DON'T CARE
WHO IT IS.
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN,
BUT I'LL BE FINE.
WOULD YOU?
[ SIGHS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ TWIG SNAPS ]
MIND IF I ASK
WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE?
YOU KNOW BETTER THAN TO GO
CLIMBING WITHOUT A PARTNER.
HOW ABOUT THAT VOLCANO WE SAW
ON THE WAY DOWN, MOUNT TAR'ANA?
TAR'HANA.
IS IT STILL ACTIVE?
-THERE ARE FREQUENT ERUPTIONS.
-OH.
WE CAN SCHEDULE A TOUR OF THE
CRATER, IF YOU'RE INTERESTED.
WOW.
VOLCANOES, ANCIENT RUINS,
FIRE PLAINS --
I'M NOT SURE WHERE TO START.
SO THIS IS WHERE YOU GREW UP.
[ WATER TRICKLING ]
IT'S NOT LIKE I IMAGINED.
MEANING?
WELL, IT -- IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
VULCANS APPRECIATE BEAUTY.
WELL,
I HAD NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
YOU ALWAYS WERE
A SNAZZY DRESSER.
COMMANDER TUCKER, I SUGGEST...
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
YOU WERE BRINGING A GUEST.
MOTHER, YOU'RE HOME.
OBVIOUSLY.
IT'S AGREEABLE TO SEE YOU.
YOU APPEAR WELL.
I'M CHARLES TUCKER.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU, MA'AM.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU BOTH MUST BE VERY TIRED
AFTER YOUR JOURNEY.
THE GUEST ROOM IS
ON THE SOUTH END OF THE HOUSE.
IT'S NOT YET MIDDAY.
WHY AREN'T YOU
AT THE SCIENCE ACADEMY?
I'M NO LONGER
AN INSTRUCTOR THERE.
I WROTE YOU A LETTER.
DIDN'T STARFLEET
TRANSMIT IT TO YOUR SHIP?
WE HAD COMMUNICATION
DIFFICULTIES IN THE EXPANSE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHY YOU'RE SURPRISED.
THIS WAS PLANNED YEARS AGO.
THERE'S MORE TO LIFE
THAN ONE'S PROFESSION.
PERHAPS YOU'LL LEARN THAT
ONE DAY.
IT SEEMS THAT I'M NOT THE ONLY
ONE WHO KNEW YOU WERE COMING.
YOU RECEIVED THIS YESTERDAY.
IT'S FROM KOSS.
DID YOU BELIEVE
HE HAD FORGOTTEN YOU?
YOU'RE GOING TO RESPOND.
I HAVE NOTHING TO SAY TO KOSS.
HE'S YOUR FIANCé.
FORMER FIANCé.
THAT IS A MATTER FOR DEBATE.
IT WOULD BE WISE
FOR YOU TO SPEAK WITH HIM.
[ INSECTS CHIRPING ]
YOU PROBABLY
DON'T WANT TO HEAR THIS,
BUT I GOT A CALL
FROM MY BROTHER YESTERDAY.
THEY RENAMED
MY OLD HIGH SCHOOL AFTER YOU.
HOW MANY IS THAT --
TWO, THREE DOZEN?
I'M NOT COUNTING.
THAT'S JUST NORTH AMERICA.
I DON'T THINK ZEFRAM COCHRANE
HAS THAT MANY SCHOOLS
NAMED AFTER HIM.
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
SO, DID YOU GET A CHANCE
TO LOOK 'EM OVER?
LOOK WHAT OVER?
MY SENIOR OFFICER CANDIDATES.
ANY SUGGESTIONS FOR TACTICAL?
YOU MAY WANT TO FIND SOMEONE
WITH MORE FIELD EXPERIENCE,
A MACO.
I'M NOT SURE HOW I FEEL ABOUT A
MILITARY OFFICER ON THE BRIDGE.
IF I WERE YOU,
I'D TALK TO GENERAL CASEY
ABOUT ASSIGNING
AN ENTIRE SQUAD.
THINGS HAVE CHANGED SINCE
ENTERPRISE LEFT SPACEDOCK.
YOU'LL SPEND A LOT OF YOUR TIME
BOLDLY GOING INTO BATTLE.
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU'RE BEING A LITTLE CYNICAL?
DID YOU READ MY REPORTS?
YES, CAPTAIN, I DID.
HEY.
[ BEEPING ]
MOUNTAIN LION.
TRACKS ARE A FEW DAYS OLD.
OOH.
GOOD THING I HAVE YOU
TO PROTECT ME.
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
COME IN.
GOOD MORNING.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
0400.
YOU'RE KIDDING.
WE HAVE TO PREPARE
THE MORNING MEAL.
AS GUESTS,
IT'S EXPECTED OF US.
OH.
THE NAH'RU VINES
HAVE BLOOMED EARLY THIS YEAR.
I'VE HAD AMPLE TIME
TO ATTEND TO THEM.
IT SOUNDS AS IF YOU'RE
NOT ENJOYING RETIREMENT.
YOU STILL HAVEN'T TOLD ME
THE REASON FOR YOUR VISIT.
I DIDN'T KNOW
ONE WAS NECESSARY.
I THOUGHT PERHAPS YOU'D DECIDED
TO REJOIN THE HIGH COMMAND.
I'VE BEEN OFFERED A COMMISSION
WITH STARFLEET.
IF I ACCEPT,
IT COULD BE SEVERAL YEARS
BEFORE I'M ABLE
TO RETURN HOME.
THE GESPAR ISN'T FRESH.
MY STASIS UNIT
NEEDS TO BE REPLACED.
HMM. WELL, I'D BE HAPPY
TO TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
IF I CAN RECALIBRATE
A WARP REACTOR,
I OUGHT TO BE ABLE
TO HANDLE A KITCHEN APPLIANCE.
MY DAUGHTER'S ALWAYS BEEN
FASCINATED BY ALIEN WORLDS.
SHE WAS ALL TOO EAGER TO FINISH
HER SCHOOLING AND LEAVE VULCAN.
AS I RECALL,
YOU ENCOURAGED ME TO LEAVE.
A MOTHER IS EXPECTED TO PUSH
HER YOUNG OUT OF THE NEST.
AT SOME POINT,
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO RETURN.
I'M TOLD THAT, ON EARTH,
A HUMAN CHILD CHOOSES
THEIR OWN PATH IN LIFE.
THEY PUT THEIR OWN WISHES
AHEAD OF THEIR FAMILY'S.
THAT'S TRUE FOR THE MOST PART.
YOU'VE LEARNED MUCH FROM THEM,
HAVEN'T YOU?
A STARFLEET POSTING
IS NO LESS IMPORTANT
THAN ONE WITH THE HIGH COMMAND.
I'M SURE FATHER
WOULD'VE APPROVED.
YOUR FATHER BELIEVED
THAT OUR WORK
SHOULD ENRICH VULCAN SOCIETY.
EARTH IS
SUPPOSED TO BE OUR ALLY.
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU?
WE SHOULDN'T ARGUE
IN FRONT OF A GUEST.
WELL, THANK YOU.
THAT IS VERY KIND OF YOU
TO SAY.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE CAN'T ACTUALLY
GIVE TOURS OF THE SHIP.
IF THAT POLICY EVER CHANGES,
YOU TWO WILL BE
THE FIRST TO KNOW.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
YOU HAD TO WEAR THAT JACKET.
DO YOU THINK I WORE THIS JACKET
TO ATTRACT ATTENTION?
HOW'S YOUR DRINK?
UM, DELICIOUS, THANK YOU.
BECAUSE I HEARD SOMEPLACE
YOUR PEOPLE DIDN'T LIKE ALCOHOL.
[ LAUGHS ] YOU MAY BE
THINKING OF VULCANS.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I GET YOUR SPECIES
MIXED UP ALL THE TIME.
IS THERE SOMETHING
WE CAN HELP YOU WITH?
I'M JUST TRYING TO MAKE SURE
YOUR FRIEND HERE IS COMFORTABLE.
SITTING IN A BAR FULL
OF SO MANY STRANGE-LOOKING
"ALIENS" LIKE US.
I'M QUITE COMFORTABLE.
BECAUSE IF YOU WEREN'T,
IF HUMANS MAKE YOU NERVOUS
FOR SOME REASON,
THE VULCAN CONSULATE'S
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE BRIDGE.
BET THERE'S SOMEPLACE THERE
WHERE SOMEONE LIKE YOURSELF
COULD GET A NICE,
REFRESHING BEVERAGE.
WELL, PERHAPS WE SHOULD,
UH, BE ON OUR WAY?
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE,
DOCTOR.
IF YOUR FRIEND WANTS TO GO,
YOU SHOULD LET HIM GO.
YOU'RE NOT CHASING
ANYONE OUT OF HERE.
YOU STARFLEET PEOPLE
ARE THE REAL PROBLEM
YOU FLY ALL AROUND SPACE
TELLING EVERY SPECIES YOU MEET
WHERE TO FIND EARTH.
DID IT EVER OCCUR TO YOU
THAT MIGHT NOT BE
THE SMARTEST THING TO DO?
SIR...
WHY DON'T YOU
JUST GO BACK TO THE BAR?
EXCUSE ME, ADMIRAL.
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS FROM YOU.
YOU HEARD HIM.
STEP AWAY FROM THE TABLE.
GENTLEMEN, PLEASE.
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
[ ALL GASP ]
DOCTOR.
I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR LETTING ME STAY HERE.
EXPRESSING GRATITUDE
IS AN EARTH CUSTOM.
T'POL SAYS "THANK YOU"
ALL THE TIME.
I'VE NOTICED.
T'POL'S LUCKY.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE A PLACE
TO GO HOME TO.
I KNOW THAT YOU'RE ROMANTICALLY
INVOLVED WITH MY DAUGHTER.
THERE'S NO LOGIC
IN DENYING IT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN ATTRACTED TO HER?
[ SIGHS ]
I KNEW WE HAD
SOME KIND OF CHEMISTRY
THE FIRST TIME
WE GOT INTO AN ARGUMENT.
I NEVER HAD FUN
ARGUING WITH ANYONE BEFORE.
I GOT THE IMPRESSION
T'POL WASN'T GONNA
SAY ANYTHING TO YOU.
SHE DIDN'T.
I'M HER MOTHER.
YOU'VE REPAIRED IT?
YEAH. THE FIELD GENERATOR
JUST NEEDED A LITTLE ADJUSTMENT.
AS GOOD AS NEW.
IF YOU HAVE THE TIME,
PERHAPS YOU COULD REPAIR
MY FOOD SYNTHESIZER?
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
WOULD YOU MIND?
KOSS?
I NEED TO SPEAK WITH T'POL.
I WANT TO HEAR ABOUT YOUR LIFE
ABOARD THE HUMAN SHIP.
YOU MUST HAVE
MANY FASCINATING STORIES.
[ WATER TRICKLING ]
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
THE ANSWER SHOULD BE OBVIOUS.
YOU'VE RECEIVED MY LETTERS.
YOU KNOW I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN MARRIAGE.
THE DECISION
ISN'T OURS ALONE.
MY PARENTS BELIEVE
IN THE OLD TRADITIONS.
FOR THEM, A BETROTHAL
CANNOT SIMPLY BE DISMISSED.
YOU HAVE THE OPTION
OF CHOOSING ANOTHER MATE.
I DON'T WANT ANOTHER MATE.
YOU SHOULD BE AWARE
I'VE BEEN ILL RECENTLY.
ILL?
IT COULD TAKE SOME TIME
FOR ME TO RECOVER,
ASSUMING IT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
I CAN HELP.
MY FATHER'S
A MAN OF INFLUENCE.
HE KNOWS THE FINEST DOCTORS
IN THE PROVINCE.
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
I INTEND TO GO THROUGH
WITH THIS.
WHAT IF I DECLARED
THE KAL-IF-FEE?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
A FIGHT TO THE DEATH?
PERHAPS YOUR HUMAN FRIEND WOULD
MAKE A SUITABLE CHALLENGER.
YOU FIND THIS AMUSING?
NO.
CALL A CHALLENGER
IF YOU WISH.
I'LL DO
WHATEVER IS NECESSARY.
IT'S BEST IF YOU LEAVE.
I MAY BE ABLE
TO HELP YOUR MOTHER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
MY FATHER COULD
HAVE HER REINSTATED.
SHE RETIRED.
SHE WAS ASKED TO RESIGN.
WHY?
I'VE SAID MORE THAN I SHOULD.
IF WE WERE TO MARRY,
YOU'D ONLY HAVE TO LIVE
ON VULCAN FOR ONE YEAR.
YOU COULD RESUME YOUR CAREER
WITH STARFLEET AFTER THAT.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT,
AN ABSENT WIFE?
I'D WANT YOU TO BE HAPPY.
YOU SHOULD GO.
[ SIGHS ]
HOW ABOUT THAT?
WHAT?
JUST TO THE LEFT OF POLARIS.
[ CRICKETS CHIRPING ]
WE FOUND OUR FIRST M-CLASS
PLANET AROUND THAT STAR.
MAYBE HUMANS WILL GO BACK
SOMEDAY, BUILD A COLONY.
I DOUBT IT. THE AIR WAS FILLED
WITH A PSYCHOTROPIC COMPOUND.
AFTER BREATHING
IT FOR A FEW HOURS,
MY SENIOR OFFICERS
NEARLY KILLED EACH OTHER.
MAYBE THE VULCANS
WERE RIGHT.
MAYBE WE WEREN'T READY.
NOT READY?
HOW LONG WERE WE
SUPPOSED TO WAIT?
LOOK WHAT IT'S GOTTEN US.
WE ALMOST LOST EARTH.
ENTERPRISE SAVED EARTH.
IF WE WEREN'T OUT THERE
STIRRING UP TROUBLE,
7 MILLION PEOPLE
MIGHT STILL BE ALIVE.
YOU WEREN'T
"STIRRING UP TROUBLE."
YOU WERE EXPLORING.
I'M NOT SURE
THERE'S MUCH OF A DIFFERENCE.
SO WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST?
PUT OUR STARSHIPS
IN MOTHBALLS?
NO. WE NEED THEM.
BUT LOOK AT THE VULCANS.
THEY'RE NOT EXPLORERS.
THEY KEEP THEIR SHIPS
CLOSE TO HOME.
YOU NEVER KNOW
WHO'S GONNA COME CALLING.
THAT'S NOT THE MISSION
EITHER ONE OF US SIGNED UP FOR.
MAYBE YOU'LL FEEL DIFFERENTLY
AFTER YOU'VE DELIVERED
A FEW DOZEN EULOGIES.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO MEDITATE
WITH YOU STANDING THERE.
THIS RETIREMENT
WASN'T YOUR CHOICE.
THAT'S NOT ENTIRELY ACCURATE.
I CHOSE TO RETIRE
RATHER THAN FACE DISMISSAL.
I WAS UNDER INVESTIGATION
BY THE SECURITY MINISTRY.
THEY CLAIMED
I HAD TAKEN RESTRICTED DATA
FROM THE ACADEMY ARCHIVES.
DID YOU?
NO.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THEIR ACCUSATIONS
WERE FABRICATED.
I WAS TOLD
THAT IF I LEFT THE ACADEMY,
THEY WOULD END THE INQUIRY.
WHY WOULD
THE MINISTRY DO THIS?
BECAUSE OF ME.
THEY BLAMED ME
FOR THE INCIDENT AT P'JEM.
AFTER THE MONASTERY
WAS DESTROYED,
THE FIRST MINISTER
WAS DISMISSED.
YOU'VE MADE
MANY ENEMIES HERE.
THEY COULDN'T REACH ME
ON ENTERPRISE,
SO THEY PUNISHED YOU.
IT'S CRIMINAL.
HOW COULD YOU
LET THEM DO THIS?
YOU'VE CHANGED.
YOUR EMOTIONS WERE ALWAYS
CLOSE TO THE SURFACE,
BUT YOU MANAGED
TO SUPPRESS THEM.
IT'S BECAUSE OF THIS
COMMANDER TUCKER, ISN'T IT?
HE'S THE REASON WHY YOU REFUSE
TO BOND WITH KOSS.
DO YOU REALLY BELIEVE
THAT A HUMAN AND A VULCAN
CAN HAVE A FUTURE TOGETHER?
IMAGINE THE SHAME
YOUR CHILDREN WOULD ENDURE,
ASSUMING THAT THE TWO OF YOU
COULD HAVE CHILDREN.
THAT WOULDN'T BE
YOUR CONCERN.
[ CRICKETS CHIRPING ]
[ FIRE CRACKLING ]
[ CREATURE GROWLING ]
[ FOLIAGE RUSTLING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ PANTING ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M NOT EVEN SURE WHAT
"ALL RIGHT" MEANS ANYMORE.
WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT?
THERE'S AN OLD CODE
AMONG CLIMBERS.
ANYTHING THAT HAPPENS
ON THE MOUNTAIN STAYS THERE.
YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHY I'M OUT HERE?
I FIGURED THIS WAS THE LAST
PLACE I'D RUN INTO ANYONE
WHO'D WANT TO SHAKE MY HAND
OR TAKE MY PICTURE
OR TELL ME I'M AN INSPIRATION
TO THEIR CHILDREN.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
IF THEY KNEW WHAT I'D DONE...
YOU DID WHAT ANY CAPTAIN
WOULD'VE DONE.
DOES THAT INCLUDE TORTURE?
OR MAROONING A SHIP
FULL OF INNOCENT PEOPLE?
BECAUSE I DON'T REMEMBER
READING THOSE CHAPTERS
IN THE HANDBOOK.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING, JON?
YOU GOING CLIMBING
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT?
-WHY NOT?
-IT'D BE A SHAME
IF YOU LOST YOUR FOOTING.
IT'S A LONG WAY DOWN.
BUT AT LEAST
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE TO DEAL
WITH THESE FEELINGS ANYMORE.
ARE YOU TELLING ME I HAVE
SOME KIND OF A DEATH WISH?
YOU TELL ME.
ALL I'M TRYING TO DO
IS GET AWAY FROM YOU.
I LOOK AT YOU, AND I SEE THE
PERSON I WAS THREE YEARS AGO,
THE EXPLORER THAT MY FATHER
WANTED ME TO BE.
[ SIGHS ]
I LOST SOMETHING OUT THERE.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO GET IT BACK.
WHAT WAS THAT?
SOMETHING I HAVEN'T DONE
IN A WHILE.
MAYBE I CAN HELP YOU FIND IT.
YOU KNOW, IF WE HAVE TIME
WHEN WE GET BACK TO EARTH,
I'D LIKE TO SHOW YOU SOME
SIGHTS, RETURN THE FAVOR.
[ VOLCANO RUMBLING ]
EVERYTHING OKAY?
THERE'S SOMETHING
I NEED TO TELL YOU.
I'VE DECIDED TO MARRY KOSS.
MARRY HIM?
IF I JOIN HIS FAMILY,
MY MOTHER WILL REGAIN
HER POSITION AT THE ACADEMY.
HIS FATHER
IS A SENIOR MINISTER
WITH A GREAT DEAL
OF INFLUENCE.
I DON'T GET IT.
ARE THEY FORCING YOU TO DO THIS?
THE DECISION WAS MINE.
MY MOTHER RESIGNED
BECAUSE OF MY ACTIONS.
WHAT?
YOU TOLD ME THREE YEARS AGO
YOU DIDN'T EVEN LOVE THIS GUY.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
LEAVE STARFLEET
AND MOVE BACK TO VULCAN?
I'VE BEEN NEGOTIATING
WITH KOSS'S FAMILY.
"NEGOTIATING"?
THEY'VE AGREED WE WON'T
HAVE TO RESIDE TOGETHER...
NOT RIGHT AWAY.
I'LL REMAIN ON ENTERPRISE
FOR THE TIME BEING.
THAT'S REAL GENEROUS OF THEM.
TRIP, I HAVE TO DO THIS...
FOR MANY REASONS.
AND HOW AM I
SUPPOSED TO TAKE THIS?
I'M SORRY.
-I --
-YOU'RE SORRY?
YOU BROUGHT ME 16 LIGHT-YEARS
JUST TO WATCH YOU GET MARRIED
TO SOMEONE YOU BARELY KNOW.
[ GRUNTS ]
WE SHOULD'VE
BROUGHT A CAMERA.
YOU REMEMBER THAT PLANET
I TOLD YOU ABOUT?
THERE WAS A MOUNTAIN RANGE
ON THE SOUTHERN CONTINENT.
THE VIEW WAS ALMOST
AS AMAZING AS THIS.
THAT'S A GOOD DAY'S CLIMB
WE'VE GOT AHEAD OF US.
WE CAN REACH THE SUMMIT
BY NIGHTFALL,
BUT WE SHOULD GET MOVING.
I THINK THE VIEW'S FINE
FROM HERE.
I'M GLAD YOU TAGGED ALONG.
YOU KNOW,
THERE'S STILL SOMETHING
I'M NOT QUITE CLEAR ABOUT.
WHAT'S THAT?
WHY DID WE STOP
SEEING EACH OTHER?
WELL, I WAS
YOUR SUPERIOR OFFICER.
IT WASN'T APPROPRIATE.
YOU'RE NOT MY SUPERIOR
ANYMORE.
I WONDER IF STARFLEET
WOULD APPROVE?
THE CAPTAINS OF
THE ONLY TWO WARP-5 SHIPS.
WELL, YOU'RE FORGETTING
THE CLIMBERS' CODE.
SO, WHAT'S THE VERDICT?
AM I GONNA LIVE?
YOUR PARASITE COUNT
IS ALMOST NEGLIGIBLE.
THIS SHOULD DISPOSE
OF THE REST OF THEM.
I HOPE YOU'RE
GONNA MAKE IT TONIGHT.
HMM?
MADAME CHANG'S.
DON'T TELL ME
THAT YOU FORGOT.
OH, UM...MY OSMOTIC EEL
IS UNDER THE WEATHER.
I SHOULD STAY ABOARD
UNTIL SHE'S FEELING BETTER.
WAIT. NO,
YOU'VE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THE EGG-DROP SOUP
AT THIS PLACE
FOR AS LONG AS
I'VE KNOWN YOU.
I'M SURE YOU AND
ENSIGN MAYWEATHER WILL ENJOY IT.
I SPOKE WITH TRAVIS.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU
THE OTHER NIGHT?
OH, YOU MUST MEAN THE, UH...
[ CHUCKLES ]
NOTHING MORE THAN AN INSTINCTIVE
DEFENSIVE RESPONSE.
SO YOU'RE GONNA STAY
ABOARD THE SHIP
BECAUSE OF SOME LOUDMOUTH
IN A BAR?
MY PRESENCE COULD PROVOKE
ANOTHER INCIDENT.
SOMEONE COULD GET HURT.
THIS ISN'T THE WAY
TO DEAL WITH PREJUDICE.
THE BEST THING
IS TO SHOW YOUR FACE
AND REMIND PEOPLE
THAT THERE ARE ALIENS
WHO DON'T WANT TO
BLOW UP THE PLANET.
I CAN'T BLAME THOSE MEN
FOR THE WAY THEY REACTED.
EARTH HAS SURVIVED
A HORRIFIC ATTACK.
IT WILL TAKE TIME
FOR THE TRAUMA TO HEAL.
BESIDES, I HAVE FRIENDS --
HMM? -- TO KEEP ME COMPANY.
NOW, IF IT'S NOT
TOO MUCH TROUBLE...
I'LL BRING YOU SOME TAKEOUT.
THE DETAILS OF THIS DEBRIEFING
WILL REMAIN CLASSIFIED,
AS ORDERED
BY THE COMMAND COUNCIL.
IF THERE ARE
NO FURTHER QUESTIONS...
AMBASSADOR.
I WANT TO APOLOGIZE FOR WHAT
I SAID TO YOU THE OTHER DAY.
I WAS OUT OF LINE.
YES, YOU WERE.
I'M GLAD WE CAN
FINALLY AGREE ON SOMETHING.
CAPTAIN.
YOUR ACTIONS, WHILE BEING
MORALLY QUESTIONABLE,
WERE NECESSARY.
I OPPOSED YOUR APPOINTMENT
AS CAPTAIN OF ENTERPRISE,
BUT IT'S OBVIOUS NOW
THAT I WAS WRONG.
T'POL HAS TOLD ME
THAT THE EXPANSE WOULD HAVE
SOMEDAY ENCOMPASSED
HUNDREDS OF SYSTEMS,
INCLUDING VULCAN.
YOU'VE DONE A GREAT SERVICE
FOR BOTH OUR WORLDS.
THANK YOU.
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
COME IN.
KOSS AND HIS FAMILY
ARE WAITING.
I'LL BE THERE
AS SOON AS I CAN.
[ SIGHS ]
KNOW ANY GOOD TAILORS?
THESE CLOTHES
BELONGED TO MY HUSBAND.
THEY FIT YOU WELL.
AREN'T YOU BOTHERED
BY THE FACT
THAT T'POL DOESN'T EVEN
CARE FOR THIS GUY?
SHE'S FULFILLING
HER FAMILY OBLIGATION.
I MET MY HUSBAND ONLY ONCE
BEFORE WE WERE JOINED.
IN TIME, WE DEVELOPED A DEEP
CONNECTION TO EACH OTHER.
YEAH.
WELL, MAYBE SHE'D RATHER
MAKE A CONNECTION
WITH SOMEONE ELSE.
HAVE YOU INFORMED T'POL?
INFORMED HER OF WHAT?
YOU'RE IN LOVE WITH HER.
VULCANS MAY NOT
EXPRESS THEIR EMOTIONS,
BUT WE ARE SENSITIVE TO THEM.
I DON'T THINK I KNEW IT
UNTIL WE WERE STANDING
OVER THAT LAVA FIELD
AND SHE TOLD ME
SHE WAS GONNA MARRY KOSS.
THAT'S WHEN IT HIT ME.
I WAS GONNA LOSE HER.
I WANTED TO TELL HER
RIGHT THERE, BUT...
[ CHUCKLES ]
...I COULDN'T.
THERE'S STILL TIME.
I THOUGHT YOU DIDN'T APPROVE.
I MAY NOT CONDONE
YOUR RELATIONSHIP,
BUT IT'S IMPORTANT FOR HER
TO HAVE ALL THE FACTS.
WELL, IF I SAY ANYTHING,
T'POL MIGHT
CALL OFF THE WEDDING...
OR WORSE, NOT CALL IT OFF.
[ SIGHS ]
SHE'S GOT ENOUGH PRESSURE
ON HER AS IT IS.
I DON'T WANT TO MAKE THINGS
ANY MORE COMPLICATED.
YOU LOOK AMAZING.
I'M GRATEFUL
THAT YOU'RE HERE.
WOULDN'T MISS IT
FOR THE WORLD.
[ GONGING ]
IT'S TIME.
WHAT YE ARE ABOUT TO WITNESS
COMES DOWN FROM
THE TIME OF THE BEGINNING
WITHOUT CHANGE.
THIS IS THE VULCAN HEART.
THIS IS THE VULCAN SOUL.
THIS IS OUR WAY.