PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
JONATHAN ARCHER.
WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE?
[ GRUNTS ]
SOMEONE ATTACKED
A KLINGON BIRD-OF-PREY.
THE ENTIRE CREW WAS MASSACRED.
THE SHIP'S MISSING.
THEY WERE AUGMENTS.
WHEN YOU REJECTED
OUR FATHER'S WISHES,
YOU STOPPED BEING
ONE OF US, RAAKIN.
OHH.
THEY'RE DANGEROUS.
THEY'RE THE FUTURE.
FATHER...
THOUSANDS OF YOUR BROTHERS
AND SISTERS
ARE WAITING TO BE BORN.
LET'S GO GET THEM.
SOME CLAIM HUMANITY ROSE UP
AGAINST THE AUGMENTS.
OTHERS SAY THE AUGMENTS
BEGAN FIGHTING AMONG THEMSELVES.
WHOEVER STARTED IT,
THE WAR DEVASTATED EARTH.
MILLIONS PERISHED.
AND WHEN IT WAS OVER...
PEOPLE LIKE YOU...WERE FEARED.
HUMANS WILL ALWAYS FEAR YOU.
THEY FEAR YOUR POWER,
YOUR INTELLECT.
THEY FEAR YOU
BECAUSE YOU'RE EVERYTHING
THEY WANT TO BE,
BUT CAN'T BE.
WHICH IS WHY I BROUGHT YOU HERE,
WHERE IT'S SAFE.
I'VE RAISED YOU LIKE MY OWN.
YOU CALL ME FATHER.
BUT I'M ONLY WATCHING OVER YOU.
YOU BELONG TO THE FUTURE,
AND SOMEDAY,
YOU WILL FULFILL
HUMANITY'S PROMISE.
MALIK.
ARE THERE OTHERS LIKE US?
MANY OTHERS,
WAITING, ASLEEP.
AND SOMEDAY, IT WILL BE
YOUR DUTY TO WAKE THEM,
SET THEM FREE.
[ BEEPING ]
WE'LL HAVE TO REACH
THIS SUBLEVEL.
SECURITY PERSONNEL ARE
LOCATED HERE AND HERE.
A DIRECT HIT
TO THIS POWER CONDUIT
WOULD DEMOLISH
THEIR LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
ALL WE'D HAVE TO DO
IS WAIT A COUPLE OF HOURS.
-NO.
-BUT WE COULD WALK IN UNOPPOSED.
WE'RE NOT GOING THERE
TO TAKE LIVES.
WHAT IF THEY DON'T
GIVE US A CHOICE?
NO ONE IS TO BE KILLED.
IS THAT UNDERSTOOD?
MALIK?
YES. UNDERSTOOD, FATHER.
RIGHT.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
DR. SOONG AND HIS AUGMENTS
HAVE ESCAPED
ON A KLINGON BIRD-OF-PREY.
WITHOUT ANY OTHER LEADS,
WE'VE PROCEEDED TO
THE COORDINATES SOONG GAVE US
WHEN WE BEGAN THIS MISSION.
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
PROTEIN RESEQUENCER.
WATER PURIFIER.
EVERYTHING YOU'D NEED
TO KEEP A SMALL COLONY
OF HUMANS ALIVE.
LOOKS LIKE THIS PLACE
DOUBLED AS A CLASSROOM.
[ SCOFFS ] IMAGINE HAVING SOONG
AS YOUR TEACHER.
[ MACHINE HUMS ]
WITH THAT AND THEIR
SCREWED-UP GENES,
IT'S NO WONDER THEY TURNED OUT
THE WAY THEY DID.
TRIP.
INTERFACES.
THEY LOOK A LOT LIKE THE ONES
WE HAVE IN OUR SICKBAY.
I'D SAY THEY TOOK MEDICAL
EQUIPMENT WITH THEM.
I NEED TO KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT KIND.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN FIND OUT.
WE'LL CHECK OUT
THE REST OF THIS PLACE.
[ BEEPING ]
I'LL BE DAMNED.
[ GRAVEL CRUNCHING ]
HOLD IT!
CAPTAIN!
LEAVE ME ALONE!
WE'RE NOT GONNA HURT YOU.
GET OUT OF MY WAY.
WE JUST WANT TO TALK.
MALCOLM.
SEE?
WE'RE FRIENDS.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
WE'RE FROM EARTH.
[ GRUNTING ]
THIS WAS RAAKIN'S.
I GAVE IT TO HIM WHEN HE WAS 5.
HE WAS A GOOD STUDENT.
HE LOVED ASTRONOMY.
WE'D SIT AT NIGHT,
AND I'D POINT OUT THE STARS.
[ SCOFFS ]
HE COULD NAME EVERY ONE.
WHERE'S YOUR BROTHER, MALIK?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN TOLD --
NO ONE WILL SAY ANYTHING.
I ONLY KNOW HE'S NOT HERE.
HE'S DEAD.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
HE TURNED HIS BACK ON YOUR WORD.
HE DIDN'T WANT TO
LIBERATE THE OTHERS.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
I killed him.
WE WERE ARGUING.
HE PULLED OUT A KNIFE.
I DREW MINE.
HE CAME AT ME.
THE NEXT THING I REMEMBER,
THERE WAS BLOOD EVERYWHERE.
[ SOBBING ]
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I TRIED TO SAVE HIM.
I-I TRIED.
HE WAS YOUR BROTHER!
[ GRUNTS ]
I'M SORRY.
FATHER.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO HURT HIM.
I'M SORRY.
[ SOBBING ]
MALIK.
[ SIGHS ]
IT'S MY FAULT.
I LEFT YOU ALONE.
NO.
I SHOULD HAVE STAYED WITH YOU.
YOU WERE JUST CHILDREN.
[ SOBBING ] N-NO, FATHER.
Shh. Shh.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Malik.
I'M SORRY.
HE'S DEHYDRATED, SUFFERING
FROM SLIGHT MALNUTRITION,
BUT OTHERWISE,
HE'S IN GOOD CONDITION.
FOR AN AUGMENT, HE DIDN'T
PUT UP MUCH OF A FIGHT.
HE ISN'T AN AUGMENT.
HE'S, UM, AN ANOMALY.
HIS D.N.A. IS SIMILAR TO
THE OTHERS, BUT NOT IDENTICAL.
HE WAS BORN WITH NONE
OF THEIR ENHANCED ABILITIES.
HOW'S THE JAW?
IT HURTS.
I'M SORRY ABOUT THAT,
BUT YOU DIDN'T GIVE ME
MUCH CHOICE.
I TOLD YOU MY NAME.
MY REAL NAME'S UDAR.
BUT MY BROTHERS AND SISTERS
CALL ME "SMIKE."
THAT'S AN UNUSUAL NICKNAME.
IT'S FROM "NICHOLAS NICKLEBY."
HIS HANDICAPPED FRIEND.
IS THAT WHY YOU WERE
LEFT BEHIND?
BECAUSE YOU'RE DIFFERENT?
I WOULD HAVE SLOWED THEM DOWN.
UDAR.
SMIKE.
I NEED TO FIND OUT
WHERE THEY WENT, THE OTHERS.
I'M NOT TELLING YOU ANYTHING.
I'M TRYING TO HELP THEM.
YOU'RE FROM EARTH.
YOU DON'T WANT TO HELP THEM.
YOU WANT TO KILL THEM.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
I WON'T BETRAY
MY BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
YOUR BROTHERS AND SISTERS
ARE IN DANGER.
THEY ATTACKED A KLINGON SHIP.
IF THE KLINGONS FIND THEM
BEFORE WE DO --
THEN MORE KLINGONS WILL DIE.
YOU'LL NEVER STOP THEM, CAPTAIN.
NO ONE WILL.
-[ BEEPS ]
-Tucker to Captain Archer.
-GO AHEAD, TRIP.
THE MISSING EQUIPMENT --
THEY WERE INCUBATORS,
artificial wombs.
HE'S DIFFERENT THAN I REMEMBER.
HOW?
THE MAN WHO RAISED US
WOULD NEVER RISK OUR LIVES
TO PROTECT A HUMAN.
HE KNOWS THE STATION.
HE USED TO WORK THERE.
HE KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING.
[ SIGHS ] WE'LL FIND OUT.
YOU SHOULDN'T DOUBT HIM.
WHY NOT?
-HE'S OUR FATHER.
-HE'S HUMAN.
HE'S NOT LIKE OTHER HUMANS.
I USED TO BELIEVE THAT.
YOU WERE LEADING US BEFORE.
AND NOW HE IS.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU CAN'T ACCEPT THAT.
WHY SHOULDN'T I LEAD?
AUGMENTS SHOULD BE LED
BY AUGMENTS.
I WON'T LISTEN TO THIS.
[ GRUNTING ] LET ME GO.
DON'T BE ANGRY WITH ME.
I'M JUST THINKING OUT LOUD.
I DON'T LIKE
WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
THEN I'LL STOP.
[ SIGHS ]
STAY WITH ME.
I THINK SOONG IS
HEADED TO COLD STATION 12.
ISN'T THAT WHERE
HE USED TO WORK?
IT'S A MEDICAL FACILITY
RUN BY STARFLEET
AND THE DENOBULANS.
HIGHLY VIRULENT DISEASES
ARE STOCKPILED THERE
FOR RESEARCH PURPOSES.
IT'S THE EMBRYOS
FROM THE EUGENICS WARS
THAT SOONG'S AFTER.
I THOUGHT SOONG
STOLE THE EMBRYOS.
HE TOOK 19.
BUT THERE ARE OVER 1,800 MORE.
THAT'S WHY HE TOOK
THE INCUBATORS WITH HIM.
WHY WEREN'T THESE EMBRYOS
DESTROYED AFTER THE WAR?
AT THE TIME,
IT WAS TOO CONTROVERSIAL.
EARTH'S GOVERNMENTS COULDN'T
DECIDE HOW TO HANDLE THE ISSUE,
SO THEY PUT THEM
INTO COLD STORAGE.
I JUST GOT OFF
WITH ADMIRAL FORREST.
WE'VE BEEN AUTHORIZED TO USE
WHATEVER FORCE NECESSARY
TO STOP SOONG.
I NEED ALL THE SPEED
YOU CAN GIVE ME.
YOU'LL HAVE IT.
This is cargo ship Corsair.
Repeat.
Medical emergency.
Situation is critical.
CORSAIR, THIS IS BARZAI,
A DENOBULAN MEDICAL SHIP.
WHAT'S THE NATURE
OF YOUR EMERGENCY?
Reactor leak. 10 crewmen
exposed to delta radiation.
[ BEEPING ]
I HAVE A FIX. I'M ABOUT
6 MINUTES AWAY FROM YOU.
[ BEEPING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
BARZAI, STAND DOWN
AND PREPARE TO BE BOARDED.
HOW'S THE PATIENT?
DOING FINE,
READY TO BE DISCHARGED.
GOOD.
I JUST REVIEWED
THE CREW MANIFEST FOR C-12.
ONE OF THE NAMES IS
DR. JEREMY LUCAS.
HE'S SENIOR MEDICAL DIRECTOR.
IN HIS LAST CORRESPONDENCE,
HE MENTIONED HE WAS
BEING TRANSFERRED.
HE DIDN'T SAY WHERE.
I THOUGHT YOU SHOULD KNOW.
I APPRECIATE IT.
CAPTAIN.
I SPENT A FEW MONTHS
AT C-12 MYSELF.
I KNOW THE SECURITY PROTOCOLS.
I'M FAMILIAR
WITH THE TECHNOLOGY.
I'D LIKE TO BE INCLUDED
IN THE LANDING PARTY.
CONSIDER IT DONE.
THANK YOU.
PHLOX TELLS ME HE'S READY
TO FREE UP THIS BIO-BED.
SO I'VE BEEN TOLD.
IF YOU'VE HAD
ENOUGH SICKBAY FOOD,
I'D LIKE YOU TO JOIN ME
IN THE CAPTAIN'S MESS.
DO I HAVE A CHOICE?
NO.
SEE YOU IN AN HOUR.
COLD STATION 12,
THIS IS MEDICAL SHIP BARZAI,
TRANSMITTING SECURITY CODE.
Barzai, we are currently
on heightened alert.
Slow to one-quarter impulse
and transmit security code.
TRANSMITTING.
[ BEEPING ]
Code confirmed.
You're clear to proceed.
WHY ARE YOU FLYING
A DENOBULAN SHUTTLE?
WHY NOT?
YOU AREN'T DENOBULAN.
[ GRUNTS ]
-[ BONE CRACKS ]
-[ SCREAMS ]
[ CHOKING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
THAT'S TRUE.
[ BEEPS ]
WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH MASKS.
[ SCOFFS ]
YOU DON'T NEED MASKS.
[ BEEPING ]
DR. LUCAS --
EH, I ASKED YOU
NEVER TO BOTHER ME
WHEN I'M WATCHING
A VIROPATHIC CYTOLYSIS.
OUR DEFENSE PROTOCOLS
JUST CAME ON.
DID YOU CONTACT SECURITY?
I CAN'T REACH THEM.
THE COMM'S DOWN.
[ BEEPING ]
THE SYSTEM'S BEEN TAKEN OFFLINE.
[ AIR HISSING ]
DOCTOR!
WHAT THE HELL?
[ ALL COUGHING ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
PHLOX TELLS ME YOU'VE BEEN
LIVING ON YOUR OWN
FOR QUITE A WHILE.
I LEFT THE CAMP
ABOUT A YEAR AGO.
YOU MUST BE PRETTY RESOURCEFUL
TO SURVIVE BY YOURSELF
OUT THERE.
IT WASN'T THAT HARD.
DIDN'T LOOK LIKE
A VERY FRIENDLY PLANET.
WHEN YOU GET BACK TO EARTH,
YOU SHOULD CONSIDER
GOING TO SCHOOL.
SCHOOL?
YOU'VE GOT
A LOT OF CATCHING UP TO DO.
HOW CAN I GO TO SCHOOL
IF I'M IN PRISON?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING TO PRISON?
I'M AN AUGMENT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
TOLD ABOUT EARTH.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE PUNISHED.
THAT'S NOT WHAT MY FATHER SAID.
SOONG IS NOT YOUR FATHER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOUR BIOLOGICAL FATHER
WAS MIKLOS KARLOVASSI.
HE WAS A GEOPHYSICIST.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
WE GOT THE INFORMATION
FROM SOONG'S COMPUTER.
[ BEEPING ]
YOUR MOTHER'S NAME WAS IRINA.
SHE WAS AN ATHLETE, DECATHLON,
WON A SILVER MEDAL
IN THE OLYMPICS.
WE'VE GOT A LOT
OF HISTORICAL DATA
ON BOTH YOUR PARENTS.
YOU'RE WELCOME TO LOOK AT IT.
COFFEE.
I'M APPROACHING
A NEW SLEEP CYCLE.
WHEN DOES YOUR
HIBERNATION BEGIN?
OH, NOT FOR ANOTHER FEW WEEKS.
BUT I WOULD LIKE TO INCREASE
MY BODY MASS BY AT LEAST 10%.
[ BEEPS ]
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I'M NOT VERY HUNGRY.
YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT DR. LUCAS?
WE'VE BEEN FRIENDS
A VERY LONG TIME.
WE'RE GETTING THERE
AS FAST AS WE CAN, PHLOX.
YOU MIGHT BE INTERESTED TO KNOW
SMIKE'S BECOME QUITE THE STUDENT
OF EARTH HISTORY.
HE'S BEEN READING UP
ON THE EUGENICS WARS.
I DOUBT SOONG GAVE HIM
THE WHOLE STORY.
[ CHUCKLES ] I'M QUITE FAMILIAR
WITH THE SUBJECT MYSELF.
HUMAN INTELLECT AND HUMAN
INSTINCT WERE OUT OF SYNC.
SO MANY PEOPLE WERE KILLED.
THE OFFICIAL NUMBER WAS
30 MILLION.
SOME HISTORIANS SAY
IT WAS CLOSER TO 35.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY EARTH
BANNED GENETIC ENGINEERING.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT CLARKE'S SYNDROME?
OH, IT'S A DEGENERATIVE BRAIN
DISORDER THAT AFFLICTS HUMANS.
MY FATHER DIED OF IT
WHEN I WAS 12.
I'M SORRY.
HE HAD FREQUENT PAIN,
HALLUCINATIONS,
HE TALKED TO PEOPLE
WHO WEREN'T THERE.
OFTEN COULDN'T RECOGNIZE ME
OR MY MOTHER.
THE LAST TWO YEARS
OF HIS LIFE...
AH.
AND YOU WERE THINKING
IF GENETIC ENGINEERING
HAD BEEN PERMITTED...
MAYBE SOONG HAS A POINT.
I'VE HAD TIME TO EXAMINE
HIS WORK MORE CLOSELY.
I'M FORCED TO ADMIT SOME
OF IT IS EXTREMELY INVENTIVE.
HE'S REALLY
QUITE BRILLIANT.
IT'S A SHAME SUCH A MAN
HAS TO REMAIN INCARCERATED.
HE BROKE THE LAW.
THAT'S WHY HE WAS IN PRISON.
AND THAT'S WHY I'M GOING TO
MAKE SURE HE GOES BACK.
DENOBULA PERFECTED
GENETIC ENGINEERING
A LONG TIME AGO,
BUT YOU NEVER CAME CLOSE
TO DESTROYING YOURSELVES.
PERHAPS WE WERE
SIMPLY FORTUNATE.
OR MAYBE YOUR INSTINCTS
HAD CAUGHT UP
WITH YOUR INTELLECT.
FOOD'S GETTING COLD.
I DON'T HAVE THE CODE.
WHEN I WAS SENIOR
MEDICAL DIRECTOR,
I HAD ACCESS
TO THOSE EMBRYOS.
THEY CHANGED THE POLICY
AFTER WHAT YOU DID.
THE ACCESS CODE
CAN ONLY BE OBTAINED
THROUGH STARFLEET COMMAND.
HE'S LYING.
I'M TELLING THE TRUTH.
DO THE LIGHTS IN YOUR OFFICE
FLICKER EVERY NOW AND THEN?
EVERY TWO HOURS.
DRIVES ME CRAZY.
FAULTY POWER RELAY.
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE HOW MANY
TIMES I ASKED THEM TO FIX IT.
10 YEARS LATER, THEY STILL
HAVEN'T DONE A THING.
PUT HIM WITH THE OTHERS.
-FATHER --
-I BELIEVE HIM.
TELL ME.
IT'S A HEXADECIMAL PASSWORD.
I'M CREATING AN ALGORITHM
TO COMPUTE THE POSSIBLE
COMBINATIONS,
A FEW HUNDRED THOUSAND OF THEM.
IT MAY TAKE A FEW MINUTES.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I HELD YOU BACK IN MATH.
[ BEEPING ]
A SHIP'S ENTERING THE SYSTEM.
RANGE, 20 MILLION KILOMETERS.
ANY SIGN OF THE BIRD-OF-PREY?
NONE.
THEY COULD BE HIDING BEHIND
ANY ONE OF THE LARGER ASTEROIDS.
-[ BEEPING ]
-WE'RE BEING HAILED.
PUT IT UP.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN. I WISH I COULD SAY
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME.
THIS ONLY ENDS ONE WAY, DOCTOR.
I THINK YOU'VE UNDERESTIMATED
THE VARIABLES,
ABOUT 11 OF THEM.
NO ONE WILL BE HARMED
IF YOU LEAVE THIS SYSTEM
IMMEDIATELY.
I'M BETTING YOU'RE NOT
A COLD-BLOODED KILLER.
TURN YOUR SHIP AROUND NOW.
I WANT PROOF THAT
THE HOSTAGES ARE UNHARMED.
LET ME SPEAK TO LUCAS.
GO AHEAD.
WE'RE ALL RIGHT.
NO ONE'S BEEN HURT.
THAT'S ABOUT TO CHANGE.
YOU'RE STILL APPROACHING
THIS STATION.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT A KLINGON DISRUPTOR
WILL DO TO A HUMAN SKULL
AT THIS RANGE?
YOU'RE GOING TO LEAVE ME
WITH AN AWFUL MESS TO CLEAN UP.
DOCTOR.
CONVERSATION'S OVER.
HE DIES.
ALL STOP!
NOW TURN AROUND.
BRING US ABOUT.
[ BEEPING ]
[ SIGHS ]
THAT'S A GOOD CAPTAIN.
THERE'S ANOTHER LAYER
OF ENCRYPTION.
IT APPEARS
TO BE ON A QUANTUM LEVEL.
HOW LONG?
LONGER THAN I THOUGHT,
MAYBE A LOT LONGER.
KEEP WORKING.
HE LIED...
DR. LUCAS, ABOUT THE EMBRYOS.
STATION ACCESS LOG.
GET HIM IN HERE.
I'VE MODULATED
THE TRANSPORTER FREQUENCY
TO MATCH THE STATION'S
CONTAINMENT FIELDS.
IF YOU REGISTER
AT ALL ON THEIR SENSORS,
IT'LL LOOK LIKE A FIELD ECHO.
DO YOU REALLY THINK I CAN HELP?
IF I DIDN'T, I WOULDN'T HAVE
ASKED YOU TO COME ALONG.
CAPTAIN, WE'RE NEARLY
OUT OF TRANSPORTER RANGE.
ENERGIZE.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ COUGHS ]
MALIK! MALIK!
I WANT TO PUT AN END TO THIS,
DOCTOR.
SO DO I.
WE KNOW YOU CAN
GET TO THE EMBRYOS.
YOU ACCESSED THE STASIS CHAMBER
JUST LAST WEEK.
THAT'S A MISTAKE IN THE LOG.
I IMPLORE YOU.
GIVE US WHAT WE CAME FOR,
AND WE'LL LEAVE YOU IN PEACE.
WHAT'S THAT?
I said...[MURMURING]
THAT LANGUAGE IS UNBECOMING
OF A MAN OF SCIENCE.
FATHER.
SOME MEN ARE BRAVER
WITH THEIR OWN LIVES
THAN THEY ARE
WITH THE LIVES OF OTHERS.
BRING IN ONE OF HIS COLLEAGUES.
NO, NOT HERE.
IN THERE.
THERE ARE THOUSANDS
OF PATHOGENS STORED HERE.
-SOME KILL WITHIN MINUTES.
-NO.
THE LONGER WE'RE
IN THIS FACILITY,
THE GREATER THE CHANCE
THAT MORE SHIPS WILL COME,
AND THEY MIGHT NOT BACK DOWN
LIKE ENTERPRISE.
IT ISN'T NECESSARY.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO MAKE HIM TALK.
IS ONE HUMAN BEING
WORTH ALL OUR LIVES
AND EVERYTHING
YOU'VE WORKED FOR?
IF THAT'S WHAT IT
TAKES TO STUN THEM,
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT TO DO
TO KILL THEM?
[ PANTING ]
[ BEEPING ]
NO, NO, NO.
[ GRUNTING ]
ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH SYMBALENE BLOOD BURN?
THE VASCULAR LINING
LITERALLY BOILS AWAY.
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
ACTUALLY, MOTHER
WAS A CHEMIST.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
BELIEVE ME, I DON'T WANT TO,
BUT I'M OUT OF OPTIONS, DOCTOR.
THE CODE!
[ PANTING ]
THIS IS ON YOUR CONSCIENCE,
THEN, NOT MINE.
[ BEEPING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ AIR HISSING ]
NO!
[ COUGHING ]
UH, LIFE SUPPORT RUNS THROUGH
THIS RELAY.
HOW LONG BEFORE THEY RUN OUT
OF AIR IN THE CONTROL HUB?
HALF AN HOUR. THEY SHOULD START
FEELING THE EFFECTS
WITHIN 10, 15 MINUTES.
WE'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT
NORMAL HUMAN BEINGS HERE.
EVEN AN AUGMENT NEEDS OXYGEN.
[ COUGHING CONTINUES ]
HIS TEMPERATURE'S
RISING QUICKLY.
BLOOD PRESSURE'S
APPROACHING CRITICAL.
THERE'S STILL TIME, DOCTOR.
JUST SAY THE WORD --
I'LL RELEASE THE ANTI-PATHOGEN.
THERE'S A FLUCTUATION IN THE
LIFE-SUPPORT RELAY ON LEVEL 4.
GO!
[ COUGHING ]
[ PANTING ]
RIGHT ABOUT NOW, HIS EXTREMITIES
FEEL LIKE THEY'RE ON FIRE
BUT IT'S THE CAPILLARIES
STARTING TO BURST.
WATCH.
[ SOBBING ]
PLEASE! LET ME OUT!
I'M ASKING YOU,
ONE DOCTOR TO ANOTHER.
STOP THIS.
I CAN'T.
IS IT WORTH THIS MAN'S LIFE?
[ SOBBING ]
I HAVE ORDERS.
I CAN SAVE HIM.
[ COUGHING ]
HOW CAN YOU LET THIS HAPPEN?!
HOW CAN YOU?!
TELL ME THE CODE!
THE CODE!
GO TO HELL!
RELEASE THE ANTI-PATHOGEN.
FATHER?
DO IT!
NO!
[ COUGHING CONTINUES ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
THAT SHOULD DO IT.
SMIKE?
DR. PHLOX MISSED SOMETHING
WHEN HE EXAMINED ME, CAPTAIN.
I DO HAVE ONE ENHANCED ABILITY.
I CAN HEAR LIKE THEY DO.
THEY'RE COMING.
[ GRUNTS ]
HE'S WRONG, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE ALREADY HERE.
THERE WAS A SPIKE,
THEN THE SIGNAL WAS GONE.
SOUNDS LIKE WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN A COMMUNICATOR GOES DOWN.
TO PREVENT US FROM GETTING
A TRANSPORTER FIX.
THEY'VE BEEN CAPTURED.
IT'S A LOGICAL CONCLUSION.
WE HAVE TO MAKE SURE.
AGREED.
[ BEEPING ]
JEREMY.
PHLOX!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
-[ GROANS ]
-DON'T MOVE.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
AM I GOING TO SPEND
THE REST OF MY LIFE
TRYING TO GET RID OF YOU?
YOU'RE GOING TO SPEND THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE IN PRISON.
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
UDAR?
FATHER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HOW IS -- HOW IS THIS --
THEY TOLD ME YOU WERE DEAD,
THAT -- THAT -- THAT --
THAT YOU WERE SICK.
THEY LIED TO YOU.
IT WAS RAAKIN'S ORDER.
WHAT WAS?
-BANISHMENT.
-WHY?
HE WASN'T STRONG ENOUGH.
YOU ALL WENT ALONG WITH THIS?
WHY ARE YOU SO SURPRISED?
WHENEVER A GROUP OF PEOPLE
START BELIEVING
THEY'RE BETTER
THAN EVERYONE ELSE,
THE RESULTS ARE ALWAYS THE SAME.
I DON'T NEED A HISTORY LESSON
FROM YOU.
YOU NEED IT FROM SOMEONE.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S ENTERPRISE.
WE HAVE YOUR PEOPLE.
I asked you not to interfere.
-NOW --
-T'POL! EXECUTE YOUR ORDERS!
[ GRUNTING ]
END TRANSMISSION.
[ BEEPS ]
BRING UP THE DATA FILE.
ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, COME IN.
THEY CUT US OFF.
WHAT ARE THESE ORDERS?
TO INITIATE THE STATION'S
SELF-DESTRUCT SEQUENCE.
IN A FEW SECONDS,
THIS PLACE WILL BE DUST.
YOU'D KILL US ALL,
RATHER THAN LET
THE EMBRYOS BE BORN.
IT WASN'T MY IDEA.
THE ORDERS CAME FROM STARFLEET,
BUT AFTER SEEING THIS,
I CAN'T SAY I DISAGREE.
WE WERE DEFENDING
OUR RIGHT TO EXIST.
YOU'VE ALREADY KILLED
OVER 25 PEOPLE.
YOUR EXISTENCE HAS
A PRETTY HIGH PRICE.
IT COULD GET HIGHER.
-[ BEEPING ]
-THE SEQUENCE IS COMING UP.
T'POL?
PROCEED.
[ BEEPING ]
TRANSMITTING.
10 SECONDS TO AUTO-DESTRUCT.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S SOME KIND
OF FEEDBACK PULSE.
IT'S THE SIGNAL WE SENT.
IT'S BEING AMPLIFIED 1,000%.
COMM'S DEAD.
THE STATION'S STILL THERE.
IT'S SAFE TO SAY WE'RE GOING TO
NEED ANOTHER PLAN.
WE'LL DESTROY IT OURSELVES.
THAT THING'S BURIED
INSIDE AN ASTEROID.
IT'S NOT THE PREFERRED SOLUTION,
BUT IT'S ALL WE HAVE.
LOAD PHOTONIC TORPEDOES.
MR. MAYWEATHER?
COURSE SET.
TAKE US IN.
[ BEEPING ]
LOOKS LIKE THIS PLACE
ISN'T TURNING TO DUST.
SORRY TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
THEY'RE FRIENDS.
I HEARD THEM TALKING.
IS THIS TRUE, DOCTOR?
LET'S FIND OUT.
NO!
LEAVE HIM ALONE!
[ GRUNTS ]
MALIK.
YOU'LL TELL US
WHAT WE WANT TO HEAR,
OR YOU'LL WATCH HIM DIE, TOO.
-[ BEEPING ]
-5,000 KILOMETERS.
LOCK WEAPONS.
[ CRASHING ]
STARBOARD NACELLE.
RETURN FIRE.
[ CRASHING ]
[ BEEPING ]
STOP. STOP!
[ GRUNTS ]
NO! NO!
I'LL GIVE IT TO YOU.
DON'T KILL HIM!
I'LL GIVE IT TO YOU!
INPUT THE CODE.
[ BEEPING ]
THE STASIS CHAMBER IS OPENING.
IT WORKED.
GET HIM OUT OF THERE.
YOU COME WITH US.
I'M GONNA STAY.
I UNDERSTAND.
I HOPE YOU HAVE
A LONG, HAPPY LIFE.
YOU TOO, FATHER.
[ DOOR OPENING ]
[ CRASHING ]
THEY FIRE, THEN MOVE OFF.
THEY'RE TRYING TO DRAW US
AWAY FROM THE STATION.
-[ CRASHING ]
-A FEW MORE LIKE THAT,
WE'RE GONNA BE A PART
OF THIS ASTEROID FIELD.
HOLD YOUR COURSE.
TARGET THE FACILITY.
[ CRASHING ]
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
I CAME HERE SO MANY TIMES
JUST...
JUST TO LOOK AT THEM.
I REMEMBER WHERE
EACH OF YOU WAS KEPT.
YOU WERE THERE,
RIGHT NEXT TO SAUL.
PERSIS, YAVAR.
IT WAS SO HARD TO CHOOSE
19 OUT OF SO MANY.
FATHER?
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D SEE THIS SIGHT AGAIN.
[ EXPLOSION ]
WE HAVE TO HURRY.
"TELURIAN PLAGUE."
I LIKE THE SOUND OF THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IDENTIFYING THE MOST
DANGEROUS PATHOGENS.
YOU'RE TAKING THEM WITH US.
HMM. CAN'T HURT TO HAVE
A LITTLE INSURANCE.
THEY'VE BEEN TRANSFERRED
TO THE STASIS MODULES.
TAKE TWO PEOPLE WITH YOU,
LOAD THEM ONTO THE SHUTTLE.
GET THEM
IN THE CONTAINMENT CELL.
[ CRASHING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
I WASN'T SURE
HOW I'D JUSTIFY KILLING YOU.
NOW YOU'VE GIVEN ME
THE PERFECT EXCUSE.
[ CRASHING ]
WHATEVER I CAN DO TO HELP.
HOLD ONTO THAT.
YOU'RE A COMPETENT FIGHTER...
BUT THAT ISN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
[ GROANS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROANS ]
I WISH I HAD TIME
TO CONTINUE OUR LITTLE MATCH.
I'M ENJOYING IT, BUT THIS WILL
BE ALMOST AS SATISFYING.
[ BEEPING ]
5 MINUTES AFTER WE LEAVE,
EVERY STASIS FIELD
IN THIS STATION WILL SHUT DOWN,
RELEASING HUNDREDS OF PATHOGENS.
I WONDER WHICH ONE
WILL KILL YOU FIRST.
STICK AROUND AND FIND OUT.
I LIKE YOU, CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T ALLOW MY BROTHER
TO DIE IN SUCH A WAY.
THIS WILL BE MUCH LESS PAINFUL.
SMIKE.
THEY'RE LAUNCHING A SHUTTLE.
[ BEEPING ]
THE BIRD-OF-PREY'S
MOVING TO INTERCEPT.
WHO'S ON THE SHUTTLE?
AUGMENTS AND ONE HUMAN.
SOONG.
FIRE TORPEDOES.
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
THEY'VE LAUNCHED A TORPEDO.
MAXIMUM THRUSTERS.
4 MINUTES TO
CONTAINMENT BREACH.
THERE'S NO WAY TO STOP IT
FROM HERE.
SOMEWHERE ELSE?
THE PRIMARY JUNCTION.
WHERE IS IT?
[ ALARM BLARING ]
[ ALARM CONTINUES BLARING ]