[T'Pol] PREVIOUSLY
ON "ENTERPRISE"...
JONATHAN ARCHER.
WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE?
[GRUNTS]
SOMEONE ATTACKED
A KLINGON BIRD-OF-PREY.
THE ENTIRE CREW WAS MASSACRED.
THE SHIP'S MISSING.
THEY WERE AUGMENTS.
YOU WERE LEADING US BEFORE.
AND NOW HE IS,
AND YOU CAN'T ACCEPT THAT.
WHY SHOULDN'T I LEAD?
AUGMENTS SHOULD
BE LED BY AUGMENTS.
WE'VE BEEN AUTHORIZED TO USE
WHATEVER FORCE NECESSARY
TO STOP SOONG.
WE KNOW YOU CAN
GET TO THE EMBRYOS.
GIVE US WHAT WE CAME FOR.
YOU'LL TELL US
WHAT WE WANT TO HEAR,
OR YOU'LL WATCH HIM DIE, TOO.
[GROANING]
EVERY STASIS FIELD
IN THIS STATION WILL SHUT DOWN,
RELEASING HUNDREDS OF PATHOGENS.
I WONDER WHICH ONE
WILL KILL YOU FIRST.
THERE'S NO WAY
TO STOP IT FROM HERE.
SOMEWHERE ELSE?
[Dr. Lucas]
THE PRIMARY JUNCTION.
[ALARM BLARING]
[T'Pol]
AND NOW THE CONCLUSION.
CONTAINMENT BREACH
IN 40 SECONDS.
HE'S ALMOST THERE.
[BEEP]
I'M AT THE PRIMARY JUNCTION.
YOU HAVE TO DIVERT
THE SECONDARY RELAYS.
[Malcolm]
The panel to the left.
I SEE THEM.
TWENTY SECONDS.
[BLARING CONTINUES]
HE'S ISOLATED THIS ROOM.
THE PATHOGENS CAN'T REACH US.
WHAT ABOUT THE CAPTAIN?
[BEEPING]
THE VENTILATION GRID
IS GOING TO CARRY THE PATHOGENS
THROUGH THE REST
OF THE STATION,
including the central core.
HOW LONG DO I HAVE?
LESS THAN A MINUTE.
[alarm blaring continues]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
[THEME SONG ENDS]
ARCHER TO T'POL.
[T'Pol] Go ahead.
Can you get
a transporter lock on me?
[BEEPING]
THERE'S TOO MUCH
INTERFERENCE FROM THE CORE.
You'll have
to get farther away.
[BLARING CONTINUES]
ARM THE PHASE-CANNONS.
TARGET EXTERIOR HATCH J-9.
CAPTAIN,
THE CORE WILL DECOMPRESS.
That's the idea.
Stand by on the transporter.
You'll only have a few seconds.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[BEEPING]
[computer] WARNING. PATHOGENS
DETECTED IN THE CENTRAL CORE.
T'POL!
[T'Pol] We're ready.
FIRE!
COMMANDER, DO YOU HAVE HIM?
YEAH!
WE NEED A MEDIC DOWN HERE.
WE'VE CROSSED
INTO KLINGON SPACE.
WHERE'S ENTERPRISE?
THEY'RE HOLDING POSITION.
ARCHER'S NOT FOOLISH ENOUGH
TO FOLLOW US.
WE WON'T BE SEEING ARCHER AGAIN.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
HE'S DEAD.
[SIGHS]
NO ONE WAS TO BE KILLED
WITHOUT MY EXPRESS ORDER!
I HAD NO CHOICE.
HE ATTACKED US, TRIED TO ESCAPE.
YOU DISOBEYED ME AGAIN.
I'LL LOCK YOU IN THE DARK PIT
YOU WON'T SEE
THE LIGHT OF DAY FOR A MONTH.
DO I MAKE MYSELF CLEAR?
YES, FATHER.
WHAT'S OUR SPEED?
HOLDING AT WARP 3.8.
[Soong] NOT FAST ENOUGH.
THE PORT INDUCER ASSEMBLY'S
BEEN DAMAGED.
GO TO ENGINEERING AND REPAIR IT.
I'M NOT AN ENGINEER.
YOU'RE A BRIGHT BOY, MALIK.
I'M SURE YOU'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
[T'Pol] FIRST OFFICER'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE EVACUATED THE AWAY TEAM
AND ALL PERSONNEL
FROM THE STATION.
THE CAPTAIN SHOWS
NO SIGN OF INFECTION.
HE'S RECOVERING IN SICKBAY.
THEY CROSSED THE KLINGON BORDER
APPROXIMATELY 2 HOURS AGO.
[Trip] SOONG'S NOT EVEN
BOTHERING TO COVER HIS TRACKS.
HE KNOWS THE KLINGONS WILL
INTERCEPT US IF WE FOLLOW HIM.
[Malcolm] THEY HAVE HALF
A DOZEN PATROLS IN THE AREA.
IS THERE SOMETHING WE CAN DO
TO KEEP FROM SHOWING UP
ON THEIR SENSORS?
I COULD PAINT
A BIRD-OF-PREY ON THE HULL.
PERHAPS WE COULD FAKE
A KLINGON WARP SIGNATURE.
I'D HAVE TO RECONFIGURE
THE COIL ASSEMBLY.
IT WOULD TAKE A FEW HOURS,
BUT IT SHOULD BE DOABLE.
WHAT'S THE STATUS OF C-12?
DR. LUCAS AND HIS TEAM
WOULD LIKE TO RETURN
AND BEGIN
DECONTAMINATION PROCEDURES.
THAT'S QUITE A MESS
THEY GOT TO CLEAN UP.
HE ESTIMATES IT WILL
TAKE MORE THAN A YEAR.
ONCE WE'RE SAFELY
THROUGH KLINGON SPACE,
WE'LL SET A COURSE
FOR THESE COORDINATES.
THE KLINGONS CALL IT
KLACH D'KEL BRAKT.
I CALL IT THE BRIER PATCH.
IT'S A LITTLE CATCHIER,
DON'T YOU THINK?
BRIER PATCH?
YOU SHOULD HAVE READ MORE
OF THE BOOKS I LEFT FOR YOU.
THE REGION IS FLOODED
WITH RADIATION
FROM SUPERNOVA REMNANTS.
KLINGONS HAVE NEVER MAPPED IT.
THERE ARE SIGNS OF AT LEAST
TWO HABITABLE PLANETS
INSIDE THE BRIER PATCH.
IT'S UNLIKELY
ANYONE WILL FIND US.
[Malik] THIS IS YOUR PLAN?
TO HIDE AGAIN?
THE EMBRYOS NEED TO MATURE
IN A SAFE ENVIRONMENT.
STARFLEET ISN'T GONNA
GIVE UP SO EASILY.
THEY'LL SEND OTHER SHIPS.
THIS GAS CLOUD WON'T PROTECT US.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT COURSE WOULD YOU SET?
I'M NOT CERTAIN.
BUT I KNOW THAT RUNNING AWAY
ISN'T THE ANSWER.
ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH THE NAME BOTANY BAY?
IT'S A PENAL COLONY
ON THE SHORES OF AUSTRALIA.
IT'S ALSO THE NAME
OF A PRE-WARP VESSEL,
LAUNCHED AT THE END
OF THE GREAT WARS.
THE SHIP CARRIED
MANY OF OUR BRETHREN,
INCLUDING KHAN NOONIEN SINGH.
BOTANY BAY IS A MYTH.
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE
IT EVER EXISTED.
ALL RECORDS
OF THE LAUNCH WERE DESTROYED.
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO BE FOLLOWED.
EVEN IF YOU'RE RIGHT,
THE SHIP WAS LOST,
NEVER TO BE HEARD FROM AGAIN.
EXACTLY MY POINT.
KHAN WAS A GREAT LEADER,
BUT HE MADE ONE FATAL MISTAKE.
HE RAN FROM HIS ENEMIES
RATHER THAN FACE THEM.
WE'VE SPENT OUR ENTIRE LIVES
RUNNING AND HIDING.
WHEN ARE WE GOING
TO MAKE A STAND?
THE MATTER
IS NOT OPEN FOR DEBATE.
ALTER OUR HEADING.
SET A COURSE 1-8-4 MARK 3.
WE'RE GOING TO THE BRIER PATCH.
I'LL BE IN MY LAB.
I WASN'T AWARE THE DOCTOR
DISCHARGED YOU.
HE DIDN'T.
WHAT'S OUR STATUS?
HOLDING POSITION
NEAR THE KLINGON BORDER.
BRIDGE TO ENGINEERING.
[Archer] Are we ready?
I'VE REALIGNED THE WARP COILS.
WE SHOULD LOOK LIKE A KLINGON
BATTLE CRUISER TO THEIR SENSORS.
BUT THIS TRICK'S
NOT GOING TO WORK
IF WE GET
WITHIN 80,000 KILOMETERS.
-UNDERSTOOD.
-[BEEPING]
TACTICAL ALERT.
TAKE US IN, TRAVIS. WARP 4.
COME IN, MALIK.
[DOOR SLAMS]
YOU ASKED FOR ME?
YOU HAVE TO STOP
CHALLENGING MY AUTHORITY
IN FRONT OF THE OTHERS.
CAN'T A SON
DISAGREE WITH HIS FATHER?
I THOUGHT WE WERE FAMILY.
I'M WILLING TO OVERLOOK
THE THINGS YOU'VE DONE.
BUT YOU HAVE TO TRUST
THAT WHAT I'M DOING
IS BEST FOR ALL OF US.
YOU USED TO HAVE FAITH IN ME.
I WAS A CHILD.
I DIDN'T KNOW ANY BETTER.
I-I KNOW IT WASN'T EASY
AFTER I LEFT --
HOW ARE THE EMBRYOS?
I'LL BE READY TO INCUBATE
THE FIRST OF THEM
IN A FEW HOURS.
YOU'RE MANIPULATING ITS D.N.A.
THESE BASE-PAIR SEQUENCES
REGULATE THE NEURO-TRANSMITTER
LEVELS IN THEIR BRAIN.
IF I CAN MODIFY THEM,
AGGRESSION AND VIOLENT BEHAVIOR
WILL BE REMOVED.
YOU'RE CHANGING ITS PERSONALITY.
I'M CORRECTING A DEFECT
IN ITS GENOME.
GENETIC ENGINEERING WAS IN ITS
INFANCY WHEN YOU WERE CREATED.
THEY WEREN'T ABLE
TO REPAIR ALL THE MISTAKES.
DID YOU FIX THESE MISTAKES
IN THE REST OF US?
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW
UNTIL RECENTLY.
WHAT RIGHT DO YOU HAVE
TO TAMPER WITH THEIR GENOME?
TRUST ME.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
YOU DON'T KNOW
THAT THIS IS A DEFECT.
MAYBE THIS IS THE WAY
OUR CREATORS WANTED US TO BE.
[BEEP]
[Persis] Father,
you're needed on the bridge.
THERE'S A SHIP
APPROACHING AT HIGH WARP.
-HAVE YOU IDENTIFIED IT?
-IT APPEARS TO BE KLINGON.
[Soong] LET'S SEE THEM.
THIS SHIP HAS MINIMAL
AFT WEAPONS.
INCREASE SPEED.
-ARM TORPEDOES.
-[BEEPING]
OPEN A CHANNEL.
[BEEPING]
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
Drop out of warp
or we'll disable you.
HE SOUNDS PRETTY CONFIDENT
FOR A DEAD MAN.
AFT TORPEDOES.
TARGET THEIR PROPULSION SYSTEMS.
-[EXPLOSION]
-[BEEPING]
-FORWARD PLATING'S HOLDING.
-RETURN FIRE.
-AFT SHIELDS AT 50%.
-WE SHOULD ENGAGE THEM.
MNH-MNH.
THEY OUTGUN US 3 TO 1.
[EXPLOSION]
FATHER!
THE DENOBULAN PILOT.
PUT HER ABOARD THE SHUTTLE.
GO!
SCAN FOR ANY PLANETS
ALONG OUR FLIGHT PATH.
THEIR WARP FIELD'S FLUCTUATING.
CONCENTRATE ALL FIRE
ON THEIR ENGINES.
[BEEPS]
THEY'VE ALTERED COURSE.
THEY'RE HEADING
FOR A PLANETARY SYSTEM.
-WE'VE REACHED THE COORDINATES.
-TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
THEY'RE MOVING
INTO A LOW ORBIT.
THEY'RE OPENING
THEIR SHUTTLE BAY DOORS.
HOLD YOUR FIRE. MAGNIFY.
BIO-SIGNS ON THE SHUTTLE?
ONE. DENOBULAN.
CAN YOU GET A TRANSPORTER LOCK?
THE ATMOSPHERE IS TOO DENSE.
-[BEEPING]
-WE'RE BEING HAILED.
[Sato] IT'S SOONG.
MURDERING HOSTAGES IS TURNING
INTO A NEW HOBBY FOR YOU.
NO ONE'S BEEN KILLED, CAPTAIN.
THAT SHIP IS CAUGHT
BETWEEN 2 THERMAL LAYERS.
IT SHOULD BE RELATIVELY SAFE
FOR 4 OR 5 HOURS.
ENOUGH TIME FOR YOU
TO MOUNT A RESCUE MISSION.
THIS ISN'T OVER, DOCTOR.
GOODBYE, CAPTAIN.
HE'S GONE TO WARP.
DISCONNECT THAT CIRCUIT
BEFORE YOU POWER THE RELAY.
YOU MIGHT DAMAGE IT.
WARP TRAIL'S BEEN DISPERSED.
ENTERPRISE WON'T BE
ABLE TO FOLLOW US.
EXCELLENT WORK.
THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
WE NEED -- FATHER!
I NEED TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
WHAT IS IT?
WE'VE UNDERESTIMATED THEM.
STARFLEET ISN'T GOING TO STOP
UNTIL THEY FIND US.
AND WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST WE DO?
TURN OURSELVES IN?
BEFORE WE LEFT C-12,
I BEAMED ABOARD TWO DOZEN
CANISTERS OF BIOGENIC AGENTS.
YOU DID WHAT?
WE CAN MODIFY A TORPEDO
TO CARRY THE PATHOGENS.
A SINGLE TORPEDO
WOULD NEVER MAKE IT
THROUGH THEIR HULL PLATING.
I WASN'T TALKING
ABOUT THE ENTERPRISE.
WE USE IT AGAINST THE KLINGONS.
THE QU'VAT COLONY
IS LESS THAN 4 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
IF WE DETONATE THE TORPEDO
INSIDE THE UPPER ATMOSPHERE,
IT'LL SCATTER THE PATHOGEN
ACROSS THE ENTIRE PLANET.
EVERY ORGANISM ON THE SURFACE
WILL BE DEAD WITHIN DAYS.
WHEN THE HIGH COUNCIL HEARS
THAT HUMANS HAVE DECIMATED
THEIR COLONY,
THEY'LL LAUNCH A COUNTERSTRIKE.
THE KLINGONS WILL KEEP
STARFLEET BUSY FOR YEARS.
WHAT YOU'RE PROPOSING
IS MASS MURDER.
THERE IS NO OTHER CHOICE.
HOW LONG WILL IT BE
BEFORE STARFLEET
TURNS TO THE KLINGONS FOR HELP
IN FINDING US?
THIS IS THE ONLY WAY
TO GUARANTEE OUR SURVIVAL.
GO BACK TO THE BRIDGE.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOU IN PRISON?
YOU'RE NOT THE MAN
WHO RAISED US.
[SCOFFS]
THE MAN WHO WAS WILLING TO DO
WHATEVER WAS NECESSARY.
RETURN TO YOUR STATION.
[Archer] CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE RESCUED THE PILOT
OF THE DENOBULAN SHUTTLE.
FORTUNATELY,
HER INJURIES WERE MINOR.
TRIP AND T'POL ARE TRYING
TO ENHANCE OUR SENSORS
IN AN EFFORT
TO FIND THE BIRD-OF-PREY.
TARGET THE DIRECTIONAL ARRAY
ON GRID 4-5-9.
HOW ARE YOUR PARENTS?
THEY'RE FINE.
THEY MOVED INTO A NEW HOUSE
IN MISSISSIPPI.
IT'S NOT LIKE THE OLD PLACE
IN PANAMA CITY,
BUT IT'S PRETTY NICE.
WHY DO YOU ASK?
YOU HAVEN'T SPOKEN OF THEM
RECENTLY.
IN FACT YOU'VE SAID VERY LITTLE
SINCE I RETURNED FROM VULCAN.
THERE HASN'T BEEN
A LOT OF TIME TO CATCH UP.
YOU ALSO HAVEN'T JOINED US
AT THE CAPTAIN'S TABLE
SINCE WE LEFT EARTH.
-WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY?
-YOU'VE BEEN AVOIDING ME.
WELL, MAYBE I HAVE.
BUT YOU GOT TO ADMIT,
IT'S A LITTLE AWKWARD.
I MEAN, YOU'RE MARRIED.
I KNOW YOU DID IT
TO HELP YOUR MOTHER,
BUT IT'S GONNA TAKE ME
A LITTLE TIME TO ADJUST.
I'M STILL ADJUSTING
TO IT MYSELF.
THIS IS GONNA SOUND STRANGE.
BUT, UM...
AS TOUGH AS IT WAS WATCHING YOU
GO THROUGH WITH THE CEREMONY,
I WAS PROUD OF YOU
FOR WHAT YOU DID.
YEAH, I GUESS
IT'S PROBABLY FOR THE BEST.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
COME ON.
IT'S NOT LIKE WE WOULD HAVE MADE
AN IDEAL COUPLE.
A VULCAN AND A HUMAN?
ROMEO AND JULIET PROBABLY
STOOD A BETTER CHANCE.
-[BEEPING]
-SUBSPACE DISTORTION.
0.4 LIGHT-YEARS.
THERE'S NO SIGN OF A WARP TRAIL.
THEY MIGHT HAVE CONCEALED
THEIR ENGINE EMISSIONS.
[BEEPS]
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
[Archer] Go ahead.
I THINK WE FOUND HIM, CAPTAIN.
YOU DON'T SOUND 100% SURE.
[Trip] It's the best we've got.
SEND THE COORDINATES
TO MR. MAYWEATHER.
LAY IN A PURSUIT COURSE.
MAXIMUM WARP.
I DON'T HAVE A LOT OF TIME.
THE AFT LAUNCH IS STILL OFFLINE,
AND FATHER WANTS ME TO --
YOU WON'T HAVE
TO ANSWER TO HIM ANY LONGER.
I'M TAKING COMMAND.
YOU CAN'T.
I'VE ALREADY SPOKEN
WITH EVERYONE ON THE BRIDGE.
THEY'RE BEHIND ME,
BUT I NEED TO KNOW
WHERE YOU STAND.
YOU HELPED ME BEFORE.
BUT THAT WAS DIFFERENT.
THIS IS OUR FATHER.
HE MAY HAVE RAISED US,
BUT THAT DOESN'T
MAKE HIM OUR FATHER.
HE'LL NEVER BE ONE OF US.
-DON'T DO THIS TO HIM.
-HE'S GIVEN ME NO CHOICE.
I HAVE A PLAN TO PROTECT US
FROM STARFLEET AND THE KLINGONS,
ND HE WON'T EVEN CONSIDER IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT HE'S DOING
WITH THE EMBRYOS?
HE'S ALTERING THEIR GENOME.
MAKING THEM WEAK AND DOCILE,
LIKE ORDINARY HUMANS.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
GO TO HIS LAB,
TALK TO HIM YOURSELF.
I KNOW HOW MUCH HE MEANS TO YOU.
I HAVE FEELINGS FOR HIM, TOO.
HE'LL BE TREATED WITH RESPECT.
YOU HAVE MY WORD.
[SIGHS]
ARE YOU WITH ME?
FATHER, PLEASE COME WITH US.
PERSIS?
FOUR OF YOU TO SUBDUE ME?
THE CREW IS UNITED BEHIND ME.
IS THAT SO?
THERE'S NO TIME FOR THIS.
YOU ALL HAVE WORK TO DO.
DON'T MAKE THIS MORE DIFFICULT
THAN IT NEEDS TO BE.
AND IF I REFUSE,
ARE YOU GOING TO KILL ME?
NO ONE ELSE HAS TO DIE.
WHAT ABOUT THE MILLIONS YOU PLAN
TO KILL WITH THAT BIO-WEAPON?
PLEASE, FATHER.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY.
LOCK HIM IN HIS QUARTERS.
[SIGHS]
[BEEPING]
A KLINGON BATTLE CRUISER
0.3 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
THEY'RE ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
[Archer] Is there a problem
with the camouflage?
NOT THAT I CAN SEE.
[Trip] Our Klingon warp
signature's holding steady.
THEY'LL BE IN VISUAL RANGE
IN LESS THAN 2 MINUTES.
UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR.
DID YOU UPDATE THE DATABASE?
IT'S BEEN PROGRAMMED
WITH SEVEN KLINGON DIALECTS.
LET'S HOPE
THIS GUY SPEAKS ONE OF THEM.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
ATTENTION, CRUISER.
IF YOU COME
ANY CLOSER TO MY SHIP,
YOU'LL BE FIRED UPON.
[Klingon] Who is this?
MY NAME ISN'T YOUR CONCERN.
[Klingon] You've entered
restricted space.
Drop out of warp
and prepare for inspection.
THE LAST TIME I CHECKED,
THIS WAS STILL
KLINGON TERRITORY.
[Klingon] No ship is allowed
to pass through this system
without authorization
on the orders
of Governor Klag.
I DON'T TAKE ORDERS
FROM A MERE GOVERNOR.
WE'RE ON IMPORTANT BUSINESS
FOR THE HIGH COUNCIL.
[Klingon]
What sort of business?
THAT MATTER IS CLASSIFIED.
[Klingon] I'm not detecting
a council transponder signal.
Perhaps you forgot
to activate it.
DO YOU EXPECT ME
TO TURN ON A TRANSPONDER
AND LET EVERY SHIP
IN THE AREA KNOW
THAT WE HAVE
THE CHANCELLOR ON BOARD?
[Klingon] Chancellor M'Rek
is on your ship?
HE HAD IMPORTANT NEGOTIATIONS
WITH THE ORIONS.
WE'RE TAKING HIM BACK TO KRONOS.
[Klingon]
The Orions. [laughing]
[Klingon] I've heard rumors
of his negotiations
with their females.
Tell me, is it true
what they say about them?
IF I WERE YOU,
I WOULDN'T BE MAKING ALLEGATIONS
ABOUT CHANCELLOR M'REK
OVER AN UNSECURE CHANNEL.
[Klingon] I meant no insult.
I'M SURE YOU DIDN'T.
IT WOULD BE BEST
IF YOU MADE NO MENTION OF THIS
TO YOUR SUPERIORS,
OR YOU MIGHT FIND YOURSELF
COMMANDING A GARBAGE SCOW.
[Klingon] Understood.
We're honored to have
the chancellor in our system.
Qapla'.
QAPLA'.
[BEEPS]
THEY'RE ALTERING COURSE.
DON'T TELL ME
IT'S VISITING HOURS.
I'M SORRY, FATHER.
IF I DIDN'T GO ALONG WITH HIM,
HE WOULD HAVE KILLED ME.
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
IF HE DEPLOYS THAT WEAPON,
HE'LL BE CONFIRMING
EVERYTHING THEY'VE SAID
ABOUT AUGMENTS
FOR THE LAST 150 YEARS.
THEY'LL DESTROY ALL OF YOU.
YOU HAVE TO HELP ME STOP HIM.
WE CAN SABOTAGE THE ENGINES
OR THE TORPEDO LAUNCHERS --
NO, WE'LL NEVER GET TO THEM.
MALIK'S POSTED GUARDS
AT EVERY VITAL SYSTEM.
YOU HAVE TO GET ME OFF THE SHIP.
I'VE DISABLED
THE INTERNAL SENSORS.
IT SHOULD BE SOME TIME
BEFORE ANYONE NOTICES
ONE OF THE ESCAPE PODS
IS MISSING.
BE CAREFUL.
HE MIGHT SUSPECT YOU.
[BEEPING]
WHAT IS IT?
AN AUTOMATED BEACON.
IT'S VERY FAINT.
[Sato] IT COULD
BE A DISTRESS SIGNAL.
CAN YOU GET A FIX ON IT?
[BANGING]
[RUMBLING]
CAPTAIN,
WHAT TOOK YOU SO LONG?
YOU HAVE TO ALTER YOUR...
YOU HAVE TO ALTER YOUR COURSE.
IS THAT SO?
MY CHILDR--
THE AUGMENTS ARE PLANNING
TO ATTACK A KLINGON COLONY.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
IN THAT ESCAPE POD?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I WAS WAITING FOR YOU.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN STOP THEM.
[SCOFFS]
I DIDN'T COME BACK BECAUSE
I MISSED OUR LIVELY DEBATES.
PLEASE, PLEASE,
YOU HAVE TO DO AS I ASK.
YOUR STORY DOESN'T SOUND
VERY PLAUSIBLE.
I THINK WE WERE GETTING CLOSE
TO FINDING YOUR AUGMENTS.
YOU MAY HAVE PUT YOURSELF
INTO THAT ESCAPE POD
TO THROW US OFF.
YOU'RE NOT SERIOUS.
YOU'VE MADE IT CLEAR
YOU'LL DO ANYTHING FOR THEM.
LIE, MURDER.
MAYBE EVEN SACRIFICE YOURSELF.
IF THE KLINGON S RETALIATE
AGAINST EARTH
IT'LL MAKE THE XINDI INCIDENT
LOOK LIKE A LOVERS' QUARREL.
WHAT DO YOU CARE
WHAT HAPPENS TO EARTH?
YOU BELIEVE YOUR CHILDREN
ARE THE FUTURE OF HUMANITY.
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN, CONTACT C-12!
THREE HUNDRED KILOGRAMS
OF BIO-TOXINS
ARE MISSING
FROM THEIR INVENTORY.
DR. LUCAS ALREADY TOLD ME
ABOUT THE MISSING TOXINS.
MALIK STOLE THEM
WITHOUT MY KNOWLEDGE.
HE'S GOING TO USE THEM
ON THE COLONY.
YOU SAW WHAT HE DID
ON THE STATION.
YOU KNOW WHAT HE'S CAPABLE OF.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW?
YOU HAD TO SEE HIM
MURDER SOMEONE IN FRONT OF YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO SAY?
THAT YOU WERE RIGHT ABOUT THEM
AND I WAS WRONG?
MAYBE THINGS
WOULD HAVE BEEN DIFFERENT
IF I'D BEEN THERE FOR THEM,
IF STARFLEET
HADN'T LOCKED ME AWAY.
NONE OF THAT WOULD HAVE
MATTERED IN THE END.
IT'S IN THEIR NATURE.
THEY WERE ENGINEERED
TO BE THIS WAY.
"SUPERIOR ABILITY
BREEDS SUPERIOR AMBITION."
ONE OF THEIR CREATORS
WROTE THAT.
HE WAS MURDERED BY AN AUGMENT.
WORK WITH SOONG.
HE'LL SHOW YOU HOW TO SCAN
FOR THEIR WARP TRAIL.
I WANT TO INTERCEPT THEM
BEFORE THEY REACH THE COLONY.
HE MAY BE LEADING US
INTO A TRAP.
I BELIEVE HIM.
THAT PLANET'S OVER
3 LIGHT-YEARS AWAY.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO PUSH THE ENGINES
PRETTY HARD
TO GET THERE IN TIME.
-IS THAT A PROBLEM?
-AT THAT SPEED,
OUR PHONY WARP SIGNATURE
MIGHT NOT FOOL THE KLINGONS.
DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO.
YOU'VE BEEN QUIET.
SOONG DIDN'T GET OFF
THIS SHIP WITHOUT HELP.
THE SENSOR GRID WASN'T DAMAGED
IN THE ATTACK.
SOMEONE TOOK IT OFFLINE
TO COVER HIS ESCAPE.
MAYBE HE DISABLED IT.
HE WOULD HAVE NEEDED
THE SECURITY CODES.
I NEVER GAVE THEM TO HIM.
IF FATHER DIDN'T DO IT,
THEN WHO?
CAN YOU THINK OF ANYONE?
LOKESH DIDN'T SEEM
THAT ENTHUSIASTIC
ABOUT YOUR PLAN
TO ATTACK THE KLINGONS.
HE'S BEEN IN THE WEAPONS BAY
FOR A DAY AND A HALF,
MODIFYING THE TORPEDO.
MAYBE I SHOULD TORTURE HIM,
JUST TO MAKE SURE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
ONLY FOUR OF US HAVE THE CODES.
OF THOSE FOUR,
YOU AND I ARE THE ONLY ONES
WHO WEREN'T ON THE BRIDGE
WHEN SOONG ESCAPED.
YOU THINK I DID IT?
YOUR HEART'S BEATING FASTER.
PERHAPS IT'S TRYING
TO TELL ME SOMETHING.
ARE YOU GOING
TO USE THAT ON ME?
IF I HAVE TO.
[SCREAMS]
[GROANS]
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE THAT.
[GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
I'LL MISS YOU.
HOW LONG
CAN WE SUSTAIN WARP 5?
AS LONG AS THE CAPTAIN
WANTS IT.
OR UNTIL WE BLOW UP,
WHICHEVER COMES FIRST.
ADJUST THE SCANNING
FREQUENCY... 15 MEGAHERTZ.
SORRY ABOUT THAT BUSINESS
WITH THE ORIONS.
HOPE YOU WEREN'T
PERMANENTLY INJURED.
WHY DON'T YOU STAY FOCUSED
ON WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
OOH, SOMEONE'S A LITTLE
PROTECTIVE OF COMMANDER T'POL.
I JUST DON'T LIKE YOU
VERY MUCH.
[BEEPING]
IS THAT THEM?
IT IS A SHIP,
BUT IT'S NOT THE BIRD-OF-PREY.
CAPTAIN ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE.
IT'S A KLINGON VESSEL.
THEY'RE ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
IT'S A LOT BIGGER
THAN THE LAST ONE.
THIS ONE'S A D5-CLASS
BATTLE CRUISER.
HOW LONG UNTIL
WE'RE IN VISUAL RANGE?
TWO MINUTES.
SAME AS BEFORE, HOSHI.
-[BEEPING]
-THEY'RE HAILING US.
[Klingon] Earth vessel.
Surrender
and prepare to be boarded.
-[EXPLOSION]
-AFT PLATING IS FAILING.
HAIL THEM AGAIN.
IF WE DON'T REACH THE COLONY
BEFORE THAT BIRD-OF-PREY,
MILLIONS OF YOUR PEOPLE
WILL BE KILLED.
I'M NOT DETECTING
ANY OTHER SHIPS.
PERHAPS YOU PLAN
TO ATTACK THE COLONY.
CAPTAIN, IF I MAY.
[SPEAKING KLINGON]
DROP OUT OF WARP
OR WE'LL DESTROY YOUR SHIP!
-I TRIED.
-[EXPLOSION]
WE MAY BE ABLE
TO SURPRISE THEM
WITH A TORPEDO
IF WE DROP TO IMPULSE.
I WOULDN'T RECOMMEND THAT,
CAPTAIN.
THEIR SENSORS ARE FAR SUPERIOR.
THEY'LL DETECT IT.
[BEEPING]
THEY'RE TARGETING OUR REACTOR.
POWER DOWN WEAPONS.
STAND BY TO DEPLOY THE GRAPPLER.
TAKE US OUT OF WARP.
THEY'VE DROPPED TO IMPULSE.
MALCOLM?
TWO MORE SECONDS, CAPTAIN.
ON MY MARK, TRAVIS.
THEY'RE CLOSING.
THEY'RE EXTENDING
A DOCKING PORT.
-MALCOLM?
-READY, SIR.
FULL IMPULSE.
THEY'RE TARGETING THE GRAPPLER.
HOLD YOUR SPEED.
SHEARING FORCE
IS APPROACHING CRITICAL.
-WE'RE LOSING THE GRAPPLER!
-HOLD YOUR SPEED.
THEY CAN'T CREATE
A WARP FIELD.
THEY'RE DISABLED.
RESUME COURSE FOR THE COLONY,
MAXIMUM SPEED.
THERE ARE 3 POPULATION
CENTERS,
TWO HERE AND ANOTHER
ON THE NORTHERN CONTINENT.
WE'LL DETONATE THE TORPEDO
OVER THE SOUTHERN HEMISPHERE.
THAT WILL ENSURE THE MAXIMUM
NUMBER OF CASUALTIES.
WHAT'S THE WEAPON
STATUS?
WE'VE MODIFIED
THE WARHEAD.
BUT WE NEED TO TEST THE GUIDANCE
PROTOCOLS BEFORE WE CAN --
[ALARM BEEPING]
THERE'S A SHIP
ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
THE ENTERPRISE.
INCREASE TO MAXIMUM SPEED.
LOAD THE TORPEDO
STAND BY TO FIRE AS SOON
AS WE DROP OUT OF WARP.
-BUT THE GUIDANCE PROTOCOLS --
-DO AS I SAY!
THEY'VE DETECTED US.
THEY'RE ACCELERATING.
STAY WITH THEM, TRAVIS.
[Trip] Tucker to bridge.
IF WE GO ANY FASTER,
THE NACELLES ARE GONNA
FLY OFF THE PYLONS.
HOW LONG UNTIL
WE'RE IN WEAPONS RANGE?
TWO MINUTES.
BUT THE BIRD-OF-PREY WILL REACH
THE COLONY IN 73 SECONDS.
TRIP.
I HEARD.
I'LL GIVE YOU WHAT I CAN.
[Malik] HOW MUCH LONGER?
GUIDANCE IS STILL OFFLINE.
WE'LL NEED TO GET CLOSER.
TAKE US INTO LOW ORBIT.
THEY'RE PREPARING TO FIRE.
TRAVIS.
ANOTHER 15 SECONDS.
TAKE US OUT OF WARP
AS CLOSE AS YOU CAN.
WEAPONS ARE STANDING BY.
TEN SECONDS.
TORPEDO'S READY.
FIRE.
THEY'VE LAUNCHED THE WEAPON.
IT WILL REACH THE ATMOSPHERE
IN 12 SECONDS.
MALCOLM.
HARD ABOUT.
A DIRECT HIT TO THE ARMORY.
WE'VE LOST HULL PLATING.
TORPEDO LAUNCHERS.
WHAT ABOUT PHASE-CANNONS?
THE AFT CANNON'S ONLINE,
JUST BARELY.
LOCK ONTO THEIR BRIDGE.
-NO, NO, NO!
-STAND ASIDE, DOCTOR.
THEIR BRIDGE IS PROTECTED
WITH DISPERSIVE ARMOR.
YOUR WEAPONS
WILL NEVER PENETRATE IT.
TARGET YOUR CANNONS HERE,
BEHIND THEIR SENSOR ARRAY.
WHAT GOOD WILL THAT DO?
THEIR MAIN PLASMA JUNCTION'S
LOCATED THERE.
A DIRECT HIT WOULD DISABLE
THEIR ENTIRE POWER GRID.
TRUST ME.
DO WHAT HE SAYS.
FIRE WHEN READY.
[SCREAMING]
[SIGHS]
[T'Pol] THEY'RE DISABLED.
ARE THEY STILL ALIVE?
-I'M READING 12 BIO-SIGNS.
-[SIGHS]
CAPTAIN, THERE'S A POWER SURGE
IN THEIR REACTOR.
[Malcolm] HE'S OVERLOADING
HIS DILITHIUM MATRIX.
HE'LL DESTROY THE SHIP.
LET ME TALK TO HIM.
[BEEPING]
MALIK. MALIK, IT'S FATHER.
Don't do this.
Some of your brothers
and sisters are still alive.
WOULD YOU RATHER
THEY WENT TO PRISON WITH YOU?
[GASPING]
The embryos.
THERE'S NO PLACE
FOR US ON EARTH
OR ANYWHERE ELSE.
Better to die here.
PLEASE, PLEASE, PLEASE!
I'LL SEE YOU SOON.
MALIK!
[BEEPING]
SIR.
[Archer] I'LL CONTACT STARFLEET
ON YOUR BEHALF.
LET THEM KNOW
THAT YOU HELPED US.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THEY'RE GONE.
ALL OF THEM.
WE'RE HEADING THE WRONG WAY.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO THE BRIG.
I'M TAKING YOU TO CREW QUARTERS.
[GRUNTING]
YOU'RE ALIVE.
YOU BETRAYED US ALL.
[GROANS]
GOODBYE, FATHER.
[GUN FIRES]
AAH!
[Archer] CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
MAY 27, 2154.
OUR ACTIONS
AT THE KLINGON COLONY
APPEAR TO HAVE
SATISFIED THE HIGH COUNCIL.
THEY'VE CALLED OFF THEIR PLANS
TO RETALIATE AGAINST EARTH.
YOU COULD AT LEAST
LET ME FINISH MY WORK
BEFORE YOU TAKE IT AWAY
AND DESTROY IT.
[Archer]
NO ONE'S DESTROYED ANYTHING.
IT'S BEING STORED
IN A SECURE LOCATION.
MAYBE SOMEDAY,
WE'LL FIGURE OUT
HOW TO USE IT
TO BENEFIT HUMANITY.
I WOULDN'T COUNT ON IT.
I'VE BEEN THINKING...
PERFECTING HUMANITY
MAY NOT BE POSSIBLE.
CYBERNETICS.
ARTIFICIAL LIFE-FORMS.
GOODBYE, DOCTOR.
I DOUBT
I'LL FINISH THE WORK MYSELF.
MIGHT TAKE
A GENERATION OR TWO.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]