SURAK.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
ADMIRAL MAXWELL FORREST'S
PERSONAL LOG.
I'VE ARRIVED ON VULCAN
HOPEFUL THAT THE HIGH COMMAND
IS FINALLY READY
TO CONDUCT JOINT MISSIONS
WITH STARFLEET.
ADMIRAL,
THE HIGH COMMAND WILL TELL YOU
ITS DECISION AT THE PROPER TIME.
AFTER ALL WE'VE BEEN THROUGH,
I'D RATHER HEAR
THE GOOD NEWS FROM YOU.
THE HIGH COMMAND HASN'T INCLUDED
ME IN THEIR DISCUSSIONS.
THEY'RE NOT TELLING
THEIR OWN AMBASSADOR TO EARTH
WHAT THEY'RE PLANNING?
WELCOME TO THE CLUB.
ADMIRAL,
I KNOW YOU FIND OUR RELUCTANCE
TO SHARE TECHNOLOGY
AND DISCOVERIES RESTRICTIVE.
I CAN THINK OF
A FEW STRONGER WORDS THAN THAT.
WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO ABOUT HUMANS.
OF ALL THE SPECIES
WE'VE MADE CONTACT WITH,
YOURS IS THE ONLY ONE
WE CAN'T DEFINE.
YOU HAVE
THE ARROGANCE OF ANDORIANS,
THE STUBBORN PRIDE
OF TELLARITES.
ONE MOMENT YOU'RE AS DRIVEN
BY YOUR EMOTIONS AS KLINGONS,
AND THE NEXT, YOU CONFOUND US
BY SUDDENLY EMBRACING LOGIC.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ BEEPING ]
I'M SURE THOSE QUALITIES
ARE FOUND IN EVERY SPECIES.
NOT IN SUCH CONFUSING ABUNDANCE.
NEXT, PLEASE.
STEP UP TO THE SCANNER.
AMBASSADOR...
...ARE VULCANS AFRAID OF HUMANS?
WHY?
BECAUSE THERE IS ONE SPECIES
YOU REMIND US OF.
VULCANS.
WE HAD OUR WARS, ADMIRAL.
JUST AS HUMANS DID.
OUR PLANET WAS DEVASTATED,
OUR CIVILIZATION
NEARLY DESTROYED.
LOGIC SAVED US.
BUT IT TOOK ALMOST 1,500 YEARS
FOR US TO REBUILD OUR WORLD
AND TRAVEL TO THE STARS.
YOU HUMANS DID THE SAME
IN LESS THAN A CENTURY.
THERE ARE THOSE
ON THE HIGH COMMAND
WHO WONDER
WHAT HUMANS WOULD ACHIEVE
IN THE CENTURY TO COME.
AND THEY DON'T LIKE THE ANSWER.
WE'RE NOT THE KLINGONS.
WE ONLY WANT TO BE
YOUR PARTNERS,
TO DO WHAT THE NATIONS OF EARTH
HAVE LEARNED TO DO --
TO WORK TOGETHER
IN COMMON CAUSE.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE FUTURE
OF RELATIONS BETWEEN OUR WORLDS
IS NOT MINE TO CONTROL.
[ EXPLOSION ]
CAPTAIN!
HERE!
[ GRUNTING ]
AH.
-[ LAUGHING ]
-OH!
-THAT'S ANOTHER GAME -- 21-TO-2.
-[ LAUGHS ]
TIME TO SWITCH SIDES AGAIN,
DOCTOR.
CERTAINLY.
THIS IS A MOST ENJOYABLE SPORT,
REMINISCENT
OF OCTRAN FERTILITY CONTESTS.
-[ DOOR OPENS ]
-OH, GOOD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
CAPTAIN...I'VE JUST SPOKEN
WITH STARFLEET COMMAND.
EXCEPT WE'RE, UH, FULLY CLOTHED,
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHICH IS PROBABLY FOR THE BEST.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
ENTERPRISE HAS ARRIVED
AT VULCAN AS ORDERED.
THREE DAYS AFTER THE BOMBING
OF EARTH'S EMBASSY,
THE DEATH TOLL STANDS AT 43,
AND I HAVE LOST MY FRIEND
ADMIRAL FORREST.
VULCAN AUTHORITIES STILL HAVE
NO LEAD ON WHO'S RESPONSIBLE.
I'M SORRY TO KEEP YOU
FROM YOUR FAMILY,
BUT I'M GONNA NEED YOU
ON THE INVESTIGATION FULL TIME.
THAT'S WHERE I PREFER TO BE.
YOUR MOTHER AND HUSBAND
WILL UNDERSTAND?
MY MOTHER HASN'T RESPONDED
TO MY COMMUNIQUéS.
IT'S NOT UNUSUAL FOR HER
TO BECOME LOST IN HER WORK.
AS FOR MY...HUSBAND,
OUR ARRANGEMENT REMAINS
UNCHANGED.
CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
I REGRET WE MEET UNDER
SUCH TRAGIC CIRCUMSTANCES.
I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE
ADMINISTRATOR V'LAS.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
ADMINISTRATOR.
I WASN'T TOLD TO EXPECT
THE HEAD OF THE HIGH COMMAND.
CAPTAIN ARCHER, ALL OF VULCAN
GRIEVES WITH YOU TODAY.
12 VULCANS DIED IN THE BLAST,
AMBASSADOR.
TO THAT END, THIS IS STEL,
CHIEF INVESTIGATOR
OF OUR SECURITY DIRECTORATE.
CAPTAIN, WE NOW HAVE SUSPECTS.
ANDORIANS?
WHY WOULD THEY ATTACK
OUR EMBASSY?
TO CREATE CONFLICT
BETWEEN EARTH AND VULCAN.
THEY DO CONSIDER US ALLIES
WHO STAND AGAINST THEM.
SO FAR, WE'VE DONE OUR BEST
TO REMAIN NEUTRAL,
AND THE ANDORIANS KNOW THAT.
THEY HAVE NOTHING TO GAIN
BY ATTACKING US.
YOU HAVE OTHER SUSPECTS?
SYRRANNITES.
I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF THAT SPECIES.
ACTUALLY, THEY'RE
A SMALL GROUP OF VULCANS.
THEY FOLLOW A CORRUPTED FORM
OF SURAK'S TEACHINGS.
SURAK I'VE HEARD OF.
HE'S THE FATHER OF VULCAN LOGIC.
EVEN AFTER 1,800 YEARS,
WE CONSIDER HIM
THE MOST IMPORTANT VULCAN
WHO EVER LIVED.
SO WHY WOULD THESE SYRRANNITES
WANT TO ATTACK OUR EMBASSY?
IT'S HARDLY AN ACT OF LOGIC.
THEY'VE BEEN VOCAL ABOUT
THEIR OPPOSITION TO GOVERNMENT,
BUT ALWAYS PEACEFUL.
OVER THE PAST YEAR,
THEIR LEADER,
A DISSIDENT NAMED SYRRAN,
HAS BECOME A DANGEROUS ZEALOT.
CAPTAIN...
I TRUST YOU TO KEEP
THIS MATTER CONFIDENTIAL.
WE DON'T SHARE IT LIGHTLY.
BUT RECENTLY, ON OUR WORLD,
THERE HAVE BEEN INSTANCES
OF VIOLENCE AGAINST NON-VULCANS.
THOUGH WE HAVE
NO CONCLUSIVE PROOF,
THERE ARE SIGNS THAT SYRRANNITES
MIGHT BE RESPONSIBLE.
IS THERE ANY EVIDENCE
CONNECTING SYRRANITES
TO THE BOMBING?
YOUR EMBASSY IS OFFICIALLY
CONSIDERED TO BE ON EARTH SOIL.
WE'VE PRESERVED THE SITE
FOR YOU TO INVESTIGATE.
IF EVIDENCE IS THERE,
THE CHIEF INVESTIGATOR AND I
FEEL CONFIDENT YOU'LL FIND IT.
I INTEND TO.
LIEUTENANT,
HERE'S THE JUNCTION ROOM.
[ GRUNTING ]
SCHEMATICS SAY
THE SECONDARY SECURITY BANK'S
RIGHT IN THERE.
[ GRUNTS ]
STILL IN ONE PIECE.
THERE'S A WEAK POWER SIGNATURE
UNDER THIS MESS.
IT'S PROBABLY
AN EMERGENCY LIGHT...
RUNNING ON BATTERIES.
[ BEEPING ]
WELL, THERE'S SOMETHING HERE --
SOME KIND
OF SURVEILLANCE RECORDER.
[ GRUNTING ]
LIEUTENANT.
THE TIMER MIGHT BE BROKEN,
BUT THAT BOMB'S ARMED.
DON'T MOVE.
THE SLIGHTEST VIBRATION
MIGHT SET IT OFF.
[ BEEPS ]
REED TO ENTERPRISE.
I NEED
AN EMERGENCY TRANSPORTER LOCK.
TWO TO BEAM UP ON MY MARK.
Acknowledged.
WHY NOT BEAM THE BOMB
OUT OF HERE.
IF THERE'S A GRAVITY SWITCH,
IT'LL DETONATE
IN THE MATTER STREAM.
Enterprise to Reed.
The transporter's locked.
Do you need assistance?
NEGATIVE, ENTERPRISE.
STAND BY.
I'M GOING TO ATTEMPT TO SCAN IT.
ATTEMPT?
YEAH.
IF I'D DESIGNED THAT BOMB,
I'D RIG IT TO GO OFF THE INSTANT
A SENSOR BEAM MADE CONTACT.
LOOK ON THE BRIGHT SIDE --
IF IT DETONATES...
WE'LL NEVER KNOW.
STEADY.
[ THUDDING ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ SIGHING ]
THERE'S VULCAN DNA
ON THESE CONTROLS.
SO MUCH FOR BLAMING ANDORIANS.
TESTING SCAN RESOLUTION.
[ BEEPING ]
THAT CAN'T BE GOOD.
OH, DAMN.
ENTERPRISE, MARK.
[ BEEPING RAPIDLY ]
ENTERPRISE!
ACCORDING TO
THE VULCAN GENOME REGISTRY,
THE DNA ON THE BOMB'S CONTROLS
WAS LEFT BY THIS WOMAN, T'PAU.
SINCE YOU HAD HER DNA ON RECORD,
DOES THAT MEAN
SHE'S BEEN ARRESTED BEFORE?
THE REGISTRY RECORDS DNA
FROM ALL VULCANS AT BIRTH.
DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT HER?
T'PAU IS
A WELL-KNOWN SYRRANNITE.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'VE GOT A SOLID START.
NOW WE NEED TO FIND HER.
CAPTAIN, T'PAU IS VULCAN.
THE SECURITY DIRECTORATE
WILL TAKE CHARGE
OF THE INVESTIGATION.
OF COURSE.
VULCAN SOVEREIGNTY.
LIEUTENANT REED
AND COMMANDER T'POL
WILL WORK WITH YOU.
THEIR ASSISTANCE ISN'T REQUIRED.
CHIEF INVESTIGATOR,
43 PEOPLE DIED IN THE BOMBING.
12 VULCANS AND 31 HUMANS.
WE WANT HER AS MUCH AS YOU DO.
THIS IS NOW
A VULCAN SECURITY OPERATION.
WE'LL INFORM AMBASSADOR SOVAL
OF ANY DEVELOPMENTS
THAT CONCERN YOU.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
HIS DEATH IS A LOSS
TO BOTH OUR WORLDS.
IF YOU'RE LOST, AMBASSADOR,
I CAN DIRECT YOU
TO YOUR SHUTTLE.
HE SAVED MY LIFE...
IN THE EXPLOSION.
HE COULD HAVE SAVED HIMSELF.
HE ALWAYS PUT...
THE MISSION FIRST.
THE LAST TIME WE SPOKE,
HE WAS ANTICIPATING THE PROSPECT
OF JOINT MISSIONS...
...HUMANS AND VULCANS
WORKING TOGETHER.
WE HAVE TO MAKE THAT POSSIBLE...
DESPITE THE HIGH COMMAND.
IT MAKES NO SENSE
TO THINK THE SYRRANNITES ARE
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS OUTRAGE.
WE HAVE DNA EVIDENCE.
RECHECK EVERYTHING, CAPTAIN.
QUESTION EVERYTHING.
AND DON'T LET THEM
KEEP YOU ON ENTERPRISE.
THE ANSWERS YOU NEED
ARE ON VULCAN.
AND HOWEVER FAR YOU HAVE
TO TAKE THIS INVESTIGATION,
YOU HAVE MY SUPPORT.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
ENTER.
IT IS AGREEABLE TO SEE YOU.
WHAT IS THE PURPOSE
OF YOUR VISIT?
DOES A HUSBAND NEED A PURPOSE
TO VISIT...HIS WIFE?
YOUR MESSAGE WAS CRYPTIC.
BY NECESSITY.
THE SYRRANNITE THREAT
HAS BROUGHT NEW SECURITY
MEASURES INTO EFFECT.
PRIVATE COMMUNICATIONS
ARE NO LONGER PRIVATE.
YOU HAVE SOMETHING TO TELL ME
THAT THE AUTHORITIES
SHOULDN'T HEAR?
SOMETHING TO GIVE YOU.
YOUR MOTHER ASKED ME
TO DELIVER IT PERSONALLY.
SHE TOLD ME THAT IT'S BEEN
IN YOUR FAMILY FOR GENERATIONS
AND NOW IT'S YOUR TURN
TO CARE FOR IT.
WHY DIDN'T SHE GIVE THIS TO ME
HERSELF?
THE NEW SECURITY CONDITIONS --
THEY'VE FORCED YOUR MOTHER
INTO HIDING TO AVOID ARREST.
MY MOTHER?
SHE'S A SYRRANNITE.
A SYRRANNITE?
AND SHE NEVER TOLD YOU?
WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS THAT SHE'S
DISAPPEARED LIKE THE OTHERS,
FACING UNJUSTIFIED ARREST.
LIKE T'PAU.
NO, THERE'S A DIFFERENCE --
MY MOTHER WANTS ME TO FIND HER.
IT'S CALLED AN IDIC.
LOOKS OLD.
IT'S BEEN MODIFIED.
[ ENERGY HUMMING ]
[ BEEPING ]
THIS IS A DESERT CALLED
THE FORGE.
THE ROUTE'S THE ONE SURAK
SUPPOSEDLY FOLLOWED.
1,800 YEARS AGO?
SYRRANNITES FOLLOW
THE SAME PATH TODAY,
SEEKING ENLIGHTENMENT.
AND YOU THINK YOUR MOTHER
IS SOMEWHERE ALONG THAT PATH?
SHE TOLD KOSS
THIS WAS A FAMILY HEIRLOOM,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN IT BEFORE.
SHE DIDN'T WANT KOSS
TO KNOW ABOUT THE MAP.
WITH ANY LUCK...
WE CAN USE THIS TO FIND
YOUR MOTHER...AND T'PAU.
CAPTAIN, HAVE YOU SEEN
THE REPORTS ON THIS PLACE?
IT'S A HELLHOLE.
IT'S A VULCAN DESERT.
I EXPECT IT'LL BE HOT.
IT'S GOT ELECTRICAL SANDSTORMS.
GEOMAGNETIC INSTABILITY IS
SO BAD, TECHNOLOGY WON'T WORK,
SO NO COMMUNICATORS,
NO SCANNERS, NO PHASE PISTOLS.
WE CAN'T EVEN BEAM YOU INTO IT.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO WALK IN.
I'LL BE CAREFUL.
YOU'VE GOT ENTERPRISE.
YOU AND MALCOLM KEEP
THE INVESTIGATION GOING UP HERE.
AND WHATEVER THE VULCANS TELL
YOU, BELIEVE THE OPPOSITE --
PRESENT COMPANY EXCEPTED.
AMBASSADOR.
CAPTAIN.
COMMANDER.
THIS SHOWS THE GAPS
IN OUR SATELLITE SURVEILLANCE
WHEN BEAM-INS CAN'T BE DETECTED.
I'M THINKING WE'RE NOT EXACTLY
CLEARED TO HAVE THIS.
HAVE WHAT, COMMANDER?
ALL I SEE IS
A STARFLEET DATA MODULE.
RIGHT.
CAPTAIN, WHAT IF SOMETHING
GOES WRONG DOWN THERE?
IT ALREADY HAS.
ENERGIZE.
[ BEEPING ]
[ ELECTRONIC HUMMING ]
THIS SITE IS CALLED GATEWAY,
WHERE SURAK SUPPOSEDLY BEGAN
HIS JOURNEY INTO THE FORGE.
YOU KEEP SAYING "SUPPOSEDLY."
YOU DON'T BELIEVE SURAK DID
THE THINGS THEY SAID HE DID?
HE BROUGHT LOGIC TO VULCAN
IN AN AGE WE CALL
THE TIME OF AWAKENING.
BUT HIS WRITINGS FROM THAT
PERIOD NO LONGER EXIST.
THERE MUST BE SOME RECORD OF IT.
OVER THE CENTURIES,
HIS FOLLOWERS MADE COPIES
OF HIS TEACHINGS.
LET ME GUESS --
WITH THE ORIGINALS LOST,
WHATEVER'S LEFT
IS OPEN TO INTERPRETATION.
YOU FIND THIS AMUSING?
I FIND IT FAMILIAR.
WE SHOULD GET MOVING.
I THOUGHT
TECHNOLOGY DIDN'T WORK HERE.
THE DAMPENING FIELD ONLY EXTENDS
A FEW HUNDRED METERS
ABOVE THE GROUND.
PATROL CRAFT CAN FLY OVER IT,
BUT THEIR SENSORS CAN'T SEE US.
NO WONDER THE SYRRANNITES
LIKE IT HERE.
WE'RE BEING STALKED.
[ SCREECHING ]
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
SEHLAT.
RUN.
[ SCREECHING ]
HIGHER GROUND.
[ PANTING ]
HIGHER.
THEY WON'T CLIMB.
[ BOTH PANTING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
HOW LONG BEFORE IT STARTS
TO LOSE INTEREST IN US?
[ SCREECHING CONTINUES ]
DAYS...AT LEAST.
THEY'RE VERY PERSISTENT
CREATURES.
WHEN I WAS A CHILD,
I HAD ONE AS A PET.
YOU HAD ONE OF THOSE?
DOMESTICATED.
THEY WERE SMALLER, SLIGHTLY.
HOW SLIGHTLY?
YOU HAVE PORTHOS.
PORTHOS DOESN'T TRY AND EAT ME
WHEN I'M LATE WITH HIS DINNER.
VULCAN CHILDREN ARE NEVER LATE
WITH THEIR SEHLAT'S DINNER.
[ SIGHS ]
I CAN BELIEVE THAT.
THE CAPTAIN ASKED ME TO
RE-EXAMINE THE DNA FROM THE BOMB
TO SEE IF ANYONE ELSE
MIGHT HAVE HANDLED IT.
YOU SAY YOU FOUND AN ANOMALY.
MM-HMM, IN THESE CHROMOSOMAL
FRAGMENTS -- HERE AND HERE.
WHAT KIND OF ANOMALY?
THESE ARE TELOMERES --
A GENETIC CLOCK, IF YOU WILL.
EACH TIME A CELL DIVIDES,
THEY GROW SHORTER.
SURE. THAT'S HOW YOU TELL
HOW OLD SOMEONE IS
FROM A CELL SAMPLE.
MM. THOUGH T'PAU'S CURRENT AGE
IS 32 STANDARD YEARS,
HER DNA RECOVERED FROM THE BOMB
HAS AN AGE OF ONLY A FEW MONTHS.
THEY USED THE DNA THEY SAMPLED
WHEN SHE WAS REGISTERED
AS A BABY?
PRECISELY. THE EVIDENCE
IMPLICATING T'PAU IS FALSE.
CAPTAIN ARCHER'S GOING AFTER
THE WRONG PERSON.
AND THERE'S NO WAY
TO GET WORD TO HIM.
DOC, TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S THE RECORDING MALCOLM
RECOVERED FROM THE EMBASSY.
ACCORDING TO THE SECURITY LOG,
THIS IS WHEN T'PAU'S BIOMETRIC
SIGNATURE WAS RECORDED.
UNDOUBTEDLY ANOTHER FABRICATION.
BUT, LOOK --
THE GUARD RECOGNIZED
WHOEVER IT WAS.
AND THAT GUARD IS YOUR PATIENT.
CORPORAL ASKWITH?
HE COULD BE OUR ONLY CHANCE
TO IDENTIFY
WHO REALLY PLANTED THE BOMB.
HE'S IN A COMA.
HIS CRANIAL INJURIES
ARE SUBSTANTIAL.
-I DON'T EXPECT HIM TO RECOVER.
-[ SIGHS ]
THERE MUST BE A STIMULANT
YOU CAN INJECT HIM WITH,
SOMETHING TO BRING HIM 'ROUND
JUST FOR A FEW MINUTES.
THERE'S ONLY SO MUCH DAMAGE
A HUMAN BODY CAN WITHSTAND.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT HIS BODY,
DOC --
WE NEED WHAT'S IN HIS MIND.
[ SEHLAT SCREECHING ]
SOUNDS LIKE THAT KLINGON OPERA
HOSHI MADE US LISTEN TO.
[ IMITATING SEHLAT SCREECHING ]
[ SEHLAT SCREECHES ]
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
THE PATH IS SAFE AGAIN.
THAT'S QUITE A TRICK.
YOU'RE A HUMAN.
JONATHAN ARCHER.
TRAVELING WITH A VULCAN.
T'POL.
CURIOUS.
MAY WE ASK YOUR NAME?
AREV.
THAT MEANS "DESERT WIND."
DOES IT?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WE COULD ASK YOU THE SAME THING.
I FOLLOW THE PATH OF SURAK
IN MEDITATION AND STUDY.
AND YOU?
I'M ON A PILGRIMAGE
TO STUDY SURAK AND LOGIC.
T'POL IS MY TEACHER.
I WELCOME YOU TO WALK WITH ME.
BUT THIS IS NO PLACE
FOR YOUR KIND.
TURN BACK.
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME,
I'LL WALK WITH YOU, TOO.
THIS DESERT IS CALLED
THE FORGE FOR A REASON.
IT WILL TEST YOU...
AND DESTROY YOU.
THE PLAIN OF BLOOD.
SOME SAY SURAK CROSSED
THIS EXPANSE
WHEN THE HOT BLOOD OF BATTLE
STILL FLOWED GREEN.
BUT WITH LOGIC...HE COOLED IT.
CAPTAIN, THE REFLECTED HEAT
IS TOO HOT FOR YOU.
[ WATER SLOSHES ]
[ SIGHS ]
I'LL STICK TO THE SAND-COVERED
PARTS WHEREVER I CAN.
[ SIGHS ]
I WON'T NEED WATER
FOR SEVERAL MORE DAYS.
YOU'D BETTER PROTECT YOUR EYES
FROM THE GLARE.
MY INNER EYELIDS WILL
PROTECT MY VISION.
MY SPECIES EVOLVED
ON THIS PLANET.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU TRIED
TO UNDERSTAND VULCAN LOGIC?
EVER SINCE I MET T'POL.
VERY WELL, STUDENT OF SURAK,
WHO SAID, "LOGIC IS
THE CEMENT OF OUR CIVILIZATION
"WITH WHICH WE ASCEND
FROM CHAOS,
USING REASON AS OUR GUIDE?"
I'M NEW WITH THIS YOU TELL ME
SOMETHING MORE BASIC, THEN?
WHAT IS KIRI-KIN-THA'S
FIRST LAW OF METAPHYSICS?
I'M FAMILIAR WITH
NEWTON'S FIRST LAW OF MOTION.
I IMAGINE
THEY'RE PRETTY MUCH THE SAME.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN TRUTHFUL
ABOUT YOUR PRESENCE HERE.
HAVE YOU?
VULCANS DO NOT LIE.
I'VE DEALT
WITH THE HIGH COMMAND.
VULCANS CAN LIE AND CHEAT
WITH THE BEST OF THEM.
THE HIGH COMMAND DOES NOT FOLLOW
SURAK'S TRUE PATH.
NO WONDER
YOU HUMANS ARE THEIR ALLIES.
FROM THE QUESTIONS HE ASKED YOU,
I BELIEVE HE IS A SYRRANNITE.
AND IT'S OBVIOUS THAT
HE DOESN'T TRUST US ENOUGH
TO TAKE US TO THE OTHERS.
THAT ONLY LEAVES ONE OPTION.
[ WATER SLOSHES ]
WE HAVE TO TELL HIM WHAT
HE WANTS TO KNOW -- THE TRUTH.
IT MAY BE TOO LATE FOR THAT.
SANDFIRE!
[ RUMBLING ]
THIS MAN'S OUR ONLY WITNESS.
HE'S COMATOSE, BRAIN-DAMAGED,
AND HE'S HUMAN.
A MIND-MELD IS DANGEROUS
UNDER THE BEST OF CONDITIONS,
BUT UNDER THESE...
LOOK, I KNOW PHLOX SAYS
THERE AREN'T A LOT OF VULCANS
WHO CAN DO THIS SORT OF THING,
BUT YOU'VE GOT TO KNOW SOMEONE
WHO COULD AT LEAST TRY.
THOSE WHO DO HAVE THE ABILITY
WON'T RISK THEIR CAREERS
BY PUBLICLY ATTEMPTING
WHAT YOU SUGGEST.
MOST VULCANS SEE MELDING
AS DEVIANT BEHAVIOR.
WHAT'S THAT GOT TO DO WITH IT?
[ SIGHS ]
EVIDENCE WILL SOLVE THIS CRIME,
NOT MIND-MELDS.
WHAT EVIDENCE?
THE DNA ON THE BOMB WAS PLANTED.
YOU CAN PROVE THAT?
I CAN.
AMBASSADOR...
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT KIND OF POLITICS
TO MESS WITH DNA RECORDS
ON VULCAN,
BUT I THINK WE'RE LOOKING
AT A DELIBERATE ATTEMPT
TO HIDE THE TRUTH.
YOU'RE SUGGESTING A CONSPIRACY.
ONE THAT COST 43 INNOCENT LIVES.
AREN'T THEY WORTH A LITTLE RISK?
THE NEEDS OF THE MANY.
[ SIGHS ]
I CAN PERFORM THE MELD.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
CAPTAIN.
OVER HERE!
HELP ME WITH THIS.
THE SANDFIRE CAN STILL REACH US.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ CRACKLING CONTINUES ]
I KNOW THIS.
HOW DID YOU GET THIS MEDALLION?
FROM MY MOTHER.
T'LES.
YOU'RE A SYRRANNITE.
THE DAUGHTER OF T'LES
SERVES ON A HUMAN STARSHIP.
WHEN DID YOU TALK WITH HER?
IS SHE SAFE?
YOU'RE THE HUMAN RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE MONASTERY AT P'JEM.
IS THAT GONNA BE A PROBLEM?
THE HIGH COMMAND DEFILED P'JEM
WHEN THEY USED IT
TO SPY ON ANDORIA.
YOU EXPOSED THEIR HYPOCRISY.
YOU SEEM TO KNOW A LOT ABOUT US.
I'M GUESSING THAT MEANS
YOU KNOW WHY WE'RE HERE.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
YOUR MOTHER IS SAFE
WITH THE OTHERS,
AT THE T'KARATH SANCTUARY.
IT'S NOT FAR.
I'LL GUIDE YOU BOTH THERE
WHEN THE STORM HAS PASSED.
I DON'T KNOW
IF THIS HAS EVER BEEN ATTEMPTED
WITH A HUMAN BEFORE.
[ SIGHING ]
MY MIND...TO YOUR MIND.
OUR MINDS ARE ONE.
OUR THOUGHTS ARE JOINED.
YES.
I SEE WHAT YOU SEE...
...THE EMBASSY.
I'M AT MY STATION...
AT YOUR STATION.
SO MANY NEW PEOPLE ARRIVING
FOR THE SUMMIT.
I DON'T RECOGNIZE THEM ALL...
...BUT SOME I KNOW.
A PACKAGE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T NEED TO SEE IT.
GO RIGHT THROUGH.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHO?
[ GASPING ]
AMBASSADOR...
WHAT'D YOU SEE?
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
HOW LONG DO THESE SANDFIRE
STORMS USUALLY LAST?
A DAY...PERHAPS TWO.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE THIS STRONG.
BUT WE'RE SAFE HERE,
AND WE'RE IN NO HURRY.
MAYBE WE SHOULD BE.
THE HIGH COMMAND BELIEVES
THE SYRRANNITES ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR BOMBING THE EARTH EMBASSY.
THAT'S NOT OUR WAY.
THEY SEEM TO THINK THAT IT IS --
THAT YOU AND YOUR LEADER
BELIEVE IN A CORRUPTED VERSION
OF SURAK'S TEACHINGS.
[ CHUCKLING ]
DID YOUR MOTHER TELL YOU
THE STORY?
OF THE IDIC?
"INFINITE DIVERSITY
IN INFINITE COMBINATION,"
WORDS THAT ARE A MERE SHADOW
OF ITS TRUE MEANING.
SURAK TELLS US THAT THE STORY
OF THE IDIC HAS NO END.
BUT IT BEGINS HERE,
AT MOUNT SELEYA.
SURAK DIED ON MOUNT SELEYA.
HIS BODY, YES.
BUT HIS KATRA WAS SPIRITED AWAY
BEFORE THE LAST BATTLE
AGAINST THOSE WHO MARCHED
BENEATH THE RAPTOR'S WINGS,
THOSE WHO WANTED TO RETURN
TO THE SAVAGE WAYS.
WHAT'S A KATRA?
SYRRANNITES CLAIM IT'S
THE ESSENCE OF A VULCAN MIND,
THAT IT CAN BE TRANSFERRED
FROM THE BODY BEFORE DEATH,
THEN STORED IN SOME MANNER.
SOME SAY SURAK'S KATRA WAS FOUND
AND NOW IS CARRIED
BY A SYRRANNITE,
SO ALL THOSE WHO MELD WITH HIM
MAY TOUCH SURAK'S MIND.
SYRRANNITES CONDUCT
MIND-MELDING?
SURAK TELLS US...
IT IS THE HERITAGE
OF EVERY VULCAN...
EVEN THOSE WHO DON'T BELIEVE
IN THE PRACTICE.
A WITNESS?
THE GUARD RECOGNIZED THE PERSON
WHO BROUGHT IN THE BOMB
WE FOUND IN THE RUBBLE.
THE SYRRANNITE WOMAN, T'PAU.
NO.
IT WAS YOU.
I WOULD LIKE TO INTERROGATE
THIS WITNESS MYSELF.
YOU'RE NOT GETTING
ANYWHERE NEAR HIM.
PERHAPS I COULD SPEAK
WITH THE GUARD.
I'M AFRAID HE'S IN NO CONDITION
TO BE QUESTIONED.
HE'S IN A COMA.
YET, HE PROVIDED
AN EYE-WITNESS ACCOUNT.
WE ACCESSED HIS MEMORIES
THROUGH A MIND-MELD.
TELEPATHIC EVIDENCE
IS INADMISSIBLE.
IT'S NOT EVIDENCE AT ALL!
YOU ALLOWED THIS DISTASTEFUL ACT
TO TAKE PLACE?
I PERFORMED IT.
[ SIGHS ]
SOVAL.
YOU'VE SHAMED VULCAN...
AND YOURSELF.
THE LAW LEAVES ME NO RECOURSE.
YOU'LL BE SUMMONED TO APPEAR
BEFORE THE HIGH COMMAND
TO ACCOUNT FOR YOUR ACTIONS.
COMMANDER. DOCTOR.
AT ONE TIME, THE HIGH COMMAND
WAS ONLY RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE EXPLORATION OF SPACE.
BUT THAT'S CHANGED.
I'VE BEEN TOLD VULCANS
HAVE NEVER BEEN EXPLORERS.
I THINK YOU'VE BEEN TOLD
MANY THINGS ABOUT US
THAT AREN'T TRUE.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
RESEAL THE ENTRANCE!
[ GRUNTING ]
AAH!
T'POL!
[ GROANING ]
EASY.
EASY, EASY, EASY.
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
LISTEN.
THE STORM IS GAINING STRENGTH.
AAH! UGH!
[ GROANING ]
AREV.
YOU MUST CARRY IT TO SANCTUARY.
CARRY WHAT?
[ GROANING ]
- TULUK TU VOKAU.
-[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROANING ]
YOU CAN'T GO BACK.
I'M NOT A FOOL, COMMANDER.
V'LAS WAS INVOLVED
WITH THE ATTACK ON YOUR EMBASSY.
HE'S RESPONSIBLE FOR BLAMING IT
ON THE SYRRANNITES.
THEN WHY TURN YOURSELF OVER
TO HIM?
IT'S THE ONLY CHANCE I'LL HAVE
TO REACH THE REST
OF THE HIGH COMMAND.
WHAT IF THEY'RE ALL IN ON IT?
IF YOU REALLY WANT
HUMANS AND VULCANS
TO WORK TOGETHER SOMEDAY,
YOU MIGHT START THINKING
ABOUT TRUSTING US.
PEACE AND LONG LIFE, COMMANDER.
[ BEEPS ]
RIGHT.
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
AREV.
[ GROANS ]
[ GROANING ]
ARE YOU INJURED?
I'M FINE.
HE...SAID SOMETHING IN VULCAN --
"VOKAU."
"REMEMBER."
REMEMBER WHAT?
I THINK HE -- HE PUNCHED ME.
OHH.
[ BREATHES DEEPLY ]
THE STORM'S OVER?
[ ENGINE HUMMING ]
THE PATROL CRAFT
ARE FLYING AGAIN.
THEY SOUND LIKE THEY'RE
CLOSING IN ON THIS LOCATION.
HE SAID WE WEREN'T FAR
FROM THE T'KARATH SANCTUARY.
WE SHOULD KEEP MOVING.
AFTER WE BURY HIM.
[ ENGINE HUMMING ]
THEY'RE FOLLOWING
A GRID SEARCH PATTERN.
NO SENSORS, BUT THEY CAN
STILL MAKE VISUAL CONTACT.
WE HAVE TO FIND COVER
BEFORE THE SUN COMES UP.
THAT WAY.
THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
THAT'S WHERE
THE SYRRANNITES ARE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
I'M GOOD FOR A FEW MORE DAYS.
CAPTAIN...YOU'RE NOT VULCAN.
RIGHT.
-[ WATER SLOSHES ]
-IT'S ALMOST DAWN.
WE NEED TO FIND
SOMEPLACE TO HIDE.
NO.
OVER HERE.
THAT WON'T HELP US.
[ ENGINE HUMMING ]
DON'T RESIST.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
[ GRUNTING ]