PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
WE ONLY WANT TO BE
YOUR PARTNERS,
TO WORK TOGETHER
IN COMMON CAUSE.
[ EXPLOSION ]
ADMIRAL FORREST
HAS BEEN KILLED.
THE DNA ON THE BOMB'S CONTROLS
WAS LEFT BY THIS WOMAN, T'PAU.
THE ANSWERS YOU NEED
ARE ON VULCAN.
AND HOWEVER FAR YOU HAVE
TO TAKE THIS INVESTIGATION,
YOU HAVE MY SUPPORT.
THIS IS A DESERT CALLED
THE FORGE.
THE ROUTE'S THE ONE SURAK
SUPPOSEDLY FOLLOWED.
THE GUARD RECOGNIZED THE PERSON
WHO BROUGHT IN THE BOMB
WE FOUND IN THE RUBBLE.
-T'PAU.
-NO.
-IT WAS YOU.
-WHAT'S A KATRA?
SYRRANNITES CLAIM IT'S
THE ESSENCE OF A VULCAN MIND,
THAT IT CAN BE TRANSFERRED
FROM THE BODY BEFORE DEATH.
V'LAS WAS INVOLVED
WITH THE ATTACK ON YOUR EMBASSY.
HE'S RESPONSIBLE FOR BLAMING IT
ON THE SYRRANNITES.
BEFORE WE ANNOUNCE
OUR DECISION,
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WISH TO SAY?
MY ACTIONS WERE TAKEN
IN THE BEST INTEREST OF VULCAN
AND THE HIGH COMMAND.
KEEPING SECRETS FROM US
IS IN OUR BEST INTEREST?
HAD I REVEALED
MY ABILITIES AS A MELDER,
MY YEARS OF SERVICE
WOULD NOT HAVE BEEN POSSIBLE.
YOUR ACCOMPLISHMENTS
HAVE BEEN NOTEWORTHY.
THEY DON'T JUSTIFY DECEPTION.
DECEPTION HAS NEVER BEEN
A STRANGER TO THIS ROOM.
I CAUTION YOU.
ONE OF OUR OWN MEMBERS
WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR BOMBING THE EARTH EMBASSY,
AN ACT WE TRIED TO
BLAME ON THE SYRRANNITES.
THAT ASSESSMENT WAS CORRECT.
OUR INVESTIGATION OF STEL
HAS REVEALED HE'S A SYRRANNITE.
I FIND THAT
DIFFICULT TO ACCEPT.
NUMEROUS DOCUMENTS
WERE DISCOVERED IN HIS HOME.
THE EVIDENCE IS IRREFUTABLE.
SYRRANNITES WERE RESPONSIBLE,
AND THEY'LL BE DEALT WITH
ACCORDINGLY.
REGARDING THE MATTER AT HAND,
YOUR POSITION IS TERMINATED
IMMEDIATELY.
YOU'RE TO SURRENDER
ALL CLASSIFIED MATERIALS
TO THE SECURITY DIRECTORATE
BEFORE LEAVING.
I REMIND YOU THAT YOUR
LOYALTY OATH IS STILL IN EFFECT.
VIOLATION OF THAT OATH --
-I'M AWARE OF THE PENALTY.
-GOOD.
IS THERE ANYTHING
ELSE YOU'D LIKE TO SAY?
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL THAT NEEDS
TO BE SAID, EXCELLENCY,
BUT NO ONE'S
WILLING TO LISTEN.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M JONATHAN ARCHER.
CAPTAIN OF THE EARTH VESSEL.
AND YOU MUST BE T'POL.
YOU ARE A LONG WAY
FROM ENTERPRISE.
I'M HERE TO FIND THE PERSON
WHO BOMBED THE EARTH EMBASSY.
HER NAME IS T'PAU.
AND SHE LOOKS
A HELL OF A LOT LIKE YOU.
I AM T'PAU.
YOU MURDERED MY FRIEND,
ALONG WITH 40 OTHER PEOPLE.
I HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH
THE DESTRUCTION OF YOUR EMBASSY.
THE EVIDENCE SAYS YOU DID.
I HAVEN'T LEFT THIS DESERT
FOR 2 YEARS.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU
ABOUT YOUR EVIDENCE?
IT TELLS ME THAT YOU'RE LYING.
YOU HAVE A LOT TO LEARN
ABOUT SYRRANNITES.
ABOUT HUMANS.
WE DON'T SIT BACK AND DO NOTHING
WHILE OUR PEOPLE ARE ATTACKED.
NO, YOU TRAVERSE
VAST WASTELANDS,
BASED ON FALSE INFORMATION.
WHAT DID YOU PLAN TO DO
WHEN YOU FOUND ME --
PLACE ME UNDER ARREST?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
IT SEEMS EVERYTHING I'VE HEARD
ABOUT YOUR SPECIES IS ACCURATE.
MOTHER.
I'M PLEASED TO SEE
THAT YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
WE HAVE A GREAT DEAL
TO TALK ABOUT.
-AGREED.
-YOU TOLD THEM
WHERE TO FIND US.
-YES.
-IS THERE ANYONE
ELSE WITH YOU?
NO.
TO HAVE CROSSED THE FORGE
BY YOURSELVES
WITH THE SANDFIRE STORMS
THIS TIME OF YEAR?
WE MET A SYRRANNITE.
HE HELPED US FIND SHELTER.
WHO WAS THIS PERSON?
HIS NAME WAS AREV.
HE WAS STRUCK DOWN
BY AN ELECTRICAL CHARGE.
HE DIDN'T MAKE IT.
HE'S DEAD?
ARE YOU CERTAIN
HIS NAME WAS AREV?
THAT'S WHAT HE TOLD US.
HIS TRUE NAME WAS SYRRAN.
HE WAS OUR LEADER.
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ SIGHING ]
CAPTAIN, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, I'M OKAY.
[ SIGHS ]
RIGHT BEFORE AREV DIED,
HE GRABBED ME.
HE...PUT HIS HAND
ON MY FOREHEAD.
I FELT SOMETHING
INSIDE...MY HEAD.
DO YOU THINK
HE WAS TRYING TO MELD WITH YOU?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT EVER SINCE,
I HAVEN'T BEEN MYSELF.
YOU PUT US ALL IN DANGER.
WHAT IF THEY'D BEEN FOLLOWED?
I ONLY WANTED HER TO KNOW
I WAS SAFE.
YOU COULD HAVE ACCOMPLISHED THAT
WITHOUT REVEALING OUR LOCATION.
I CAN'T CHANGE WHAT I'VE DONE.
SHE DOESN'T DESERVE
IMPRISONMENT.
I WANT HER RELEASED.
NOT UNTIL WE'VE CONFIRMED
THEIR STORY.
MY DAUGHTER WOULDN'T LIE.
SHE'S NOT MERELY
YOUR DAUGHTER --
SHE'S A MEMBER OF STARFLEET,
AND STARFLEET IS ALLIED
WITH THE HIGH COMMAND.
THEY'LL BOTH REMAIN
WHERE THEY ARE
UNTIL I'M SATISFIED
THEY CAN BE TRUSTED.
[ ENGINE HUMMING ]
THE SEARCH PATROLS
ARE FLYING DAY AND NIGHT.
THEY'RE THE LEAST
OF OUR WORRIES NOW.
IF SYRRAN IS DEAD...
...THEN EVERYTHING
WE'VE WORKED FOR IS LOST.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY THREW YOU OUT.
JUST BECAUSE YOU HELPED US?
I KNEW THE RISKS.
THERE'S GOT TO BE SOME WAY
YOU CAN FIGHT THIS.
I COULD PROTEST, BUT IT WOULDN'T
ACCOMPLISH ANYTHING.
V'LAS ISN'T ONE
TO CHANGE HIS MIND.
WHO THE HELL PUT HIM IN CHARGE,
ANYWAY?
OUR SOCIETY REWARDS MERIT.
V'LAS HAS DEMONSTRATED
A SINGULAR TALENT FOR GOVERNING.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO NOW?
IF YOU'RE REFERRING
TO MY CAREER,
I HAVEN'T GIVEN IT
MUCH THOUGHT.
THERE'S SOMETHING MORE IMPORTANT
WE NEED TO DISCUSS.
HAVE YOU MADE CONTACT
WITH T'POL OR YOUR CAPTAIN?
WE CAN'T REACH THEM,
AND THEY CAN'T REACH US.
V'LAS IS DETERMINED
TO WIPE OUT THE SYRRANNITES.
HE'S PARTICULARLY INTENT
ON DESTROYING
THEIR ENCAMPMENT IN THE FORGE.
WHERE THE CAPTAIN
AND T'POL ARE HEADED.
THEY MAY BE IN GRAVE DANGER.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
YOU MUST HAVE
QUESTIONS FOR ME.
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND HOW YOU COULD
JOIN THESE PEOPLE.
I'VE BEEN GROWING DISILLUSIONED
WITH VULCAN SOCIETY
FOR SOME TIME.
WHEN I WAS FORCED
TO RESIGN FROM THE ACADEMY,
I-I BEGAN SERIOUSLY
TO QUESTION MY BELIEFS.
AND THIS IS WHERE YOU CAME
FOR ANSWERS?
SYRRANNITES BELIEVE
THAT THE VULCANS HAVE STRAYED
FROM THE TEACHINGS OF SURAK.
CONSIDERING
WHAT THE HIGH COMMAND HAS DONE
IN RECENT YEARS --
THE -- THE LISTENING STATION
AT P'JEM,
THE SUPPRESSION OF DISSENT --
OUR POSITION
ISN'T SO HARD TO ACCEPT.
YOU COULD HAVE TOLD ME ALL THIS
WHEN I CAME TO VISIT.
THE HIGH COMMAND
WAS JUST BEGINNING
TO HUNT DOWN
SUSPECTED SYRRANNITES.
I WAS AFRAID I WOULD BE NEXT.
I WANTED TO KEEP YOU
OUT OF IT.
I KNOW YOUR MARRIAGE TO KOSS
WAS FOR MY SAKE,
TO HELP ME REGAIN MY POST.
I DON'T WANT YOUR APOLOGIES,
MOTHER.
I WANT YOU
TO COME BACK WITH ME.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
[ SIGHS ]
WHEN YOU GAVE ME THAT MAP,
YOU KNEW I'D TRY TO FIND YOU.
I THOUGHT THAT,
IF YOU COULD SEE WHAT
WE WERE TRYING TO ACCOMPLISH...
THAT I'D UNDERSTAND?
THAT I'D JOIN YOU?
I HELD OUT THAT HOPE, YES.
IT'S POSSIBLE
I WAS BEING FOOLISH.
EXTREMELY.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
WAR IS TAKING ITS TOLL.
VULCAN IS TEARING ITSELF APART.
WHO ARE YOU?
YOU KNOW WHO I AM, CAPTAIN.
[ EXPLOSION ]
SO MUCH DEATH.
HARD TO BELIEVE THIS WILL BECOME
KNOWN AS THE TIME OF AWAKENING.
THAT WAS 1,800 YEARS AGO.
THIS DOESN'T FEEL LIKE A DREAM.
YOU'RE SEEING THE PAST
THROUGH MY EYES.
SYRRAN DID SOMETHING TO ME
BEFORE HE DIED.
HE CHOSE YOU.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU DON'T TRUST VULCANS,
CAPTAIN.
GIVEN YOUR EXPERIENCES WITH
THEM, I CAN'T SAY I BLAME YOU.
THE CULTURE YOU'VE COME TO KNOW
ISN'T THE ONE
I HELPED TO CREATE.
MY PEOPLE HAVE STRAYED,
AND SOMEONE MUST RESTORE THEM
TO THE PATH.
YOU'VE GOT THE WRONG MAN.
SORRY, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S AN EARTH EXPRESSION --
"WE'RE STUCK WITH EACH OTHER."
DON'T FIGHT
WHAT'S BEEN GIVEN TO YOU.
OPEN YOUR MIND AND YOUR HEART,
AND THE WAY WILL BECOME CLEAR.
CAPTAIN.
WE'VE PINPOINTED THEIR LOCATION
NEAR THE NORTHEASTERN BORDER
OF THE FORGE.
HOW ACCURATE
IS THIS INFORMATION?
IT'S BASED ON DATA COLLECTED
BY SEARCH PATROLS.
THEY'VE BEEN CONDUCTING MISSIONS
FOR SEVERAL DAYS.
WE'RE GOING TO BOMBARD
THE CAMP...
WITH PHOTONIC WEAPONS.
OUR GOAL ISN'T TO EXTERMINATE
THESE PEOPLE.
OUR GOAL IS TO MAINTAIN ORDER.
THEY'RE IN THE DEEP DESERT.
WHAT POSSIBLE HARM
COULD THEY DO US?
THEY'VE ALREADY DESTROYED
AN EMBASSY.
EVENTUALLY, THEY'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO LEAVE THE FORGE,
AND WHEN THEY DO,
WE CAN APPREHEND THEM
WITH LITTLE OR NO LOSS OF LIFE.
IT'S VERY LIKELY THAT SYRRAN
HIMSELF IS INSIDE THE COMPOUND.
WITH ONE DECISIVE THRUST,
WE CAN CRIPPLE THIS INSURGENCY,
PERHAPS END IT.
WE CAN'T LET AN OPPORTUNITY
LIKE THIS PASS US BY.
A SURGICAL STRIKE
COULD MINIMIZE THE LOSS OF LIFE.
THE GEOMAGNETIC ANOMALIES MAKE
A PRECISION ATTACK IMPOSSIBLE.
THIS IS THE ONLY WAY.
WE'LL BEGIN PREPARATIONS
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS MAN --
DID HE TELL YOU HIS NAME?
HE SEEMED TO THINK
I KNEW WHO HE WAS.
DID YOU?
IT WAS SURAK.
WE BELIEVE YOU.
SYRRAN POSSESSED
THE KATRA OF SURAK.
KATRAS ARE NOTHING MORE
THAN A MYTH.
I USED TO THINK THAT
UNTIL I LEARNED TO OPEN UP
MY MIND TO OTHER POSSIBILITIES.
IF SYRRAN KNEW
HE WAS CLOSE TO DEATH,
HE WOULD HAVE TRIED TO TRANSFER
THE KATRA TO SOMEONE ELSE.
I WAS NEAR HIM WHEN HE DIED.
THERE IS ONLY ONE WAY
TO BE CERTAIN.
I HAVE TO MELD WITH YOU.
I'VE HAD MY FILL
OF MIND-MELDS.
THE PROSPECT
DOESN'T APPEAL TO ME, EITHER.
I'VE NEVER MELDED
WITH A HUMAN BEFORE.
YOUR UNCHECKED EMOTIONS WILL,
NO DOUBT, PROVE DISTASTEFUL.
HOWEVER,
I ASK YOUR INDULGENCE.
MY MIND...TO YOUR MIND.
MY THOUGHTS TO YOUR THOUGHTS.
OUR MINDS ARE MERGING.
-OUR MINDS ARE ONE.
WE'RE IN THE DESERT.
THERE'S A STORM.
WE FIND REFUGE I-IN A CAVE.
SAND-LIGHTNING.
OUR MINDS ARE NOT ALONE.
THERE'S SOMEONE ELSE HERE
WITH US.
I SENSE HIS PRESENCE.
[ GASPING ]
T'PAU?
HE HAS THE KATRA.
WE CAN TRIGGER A MALFUNCTION IN
THIS SATELLITE'S IMAGING NODE.
IT'LL TAKE 6 MINUTES
FOR THE CENTRAL PROCESSOR
TO CORRECT THE ERROR.
THAT SHOULD BE ENOUGH TIME
TO SLIP THROUGH THE NET.
WON'T THEY WONDER
WHAT CAUSED THE GLITCH?
ERRORS OCCUR FREQUENTLY
NEAR THE FORGE.
IT SHOULDN'T RAISE SUSPICION.
[ BEEPING ]
MIND IF I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
I NEVER GOT THE IMPRESSION YOU
CARED THAT MUCH ABOUT HUMANS.
SEEMS LIKE...
YOU WERE ALWAYS FINDING
SOMETHING NEW TO COMPLAIN ABOUT.
I LIVED ON EARTH FOR
MORE THAN 30 YEARS, COMMANDER.
IN THAT TIME,
I DEVELOPED AN AFFINITY
FOR YOUR WORLD AND ITS PEOPLE.
YOU DID A PRETTY GOOD JOB
OF HIDING IT.
-THANK YOU.
-[ BEEPING ]
Launch Bay to
Commander Tucker.
GO AHEAD, TRAVIS.
WE SHOULD BE READY
WITHIN THE HOUR.
What about helm control?
I'VE RIGGED UP
A STICK-AND-RUDDER SYSTEM.
IT'LL GET US
WHERE WE WANT TO GO,
but I can't promise
a smooth ride.
JUST DON'T TELL MALCOLM
ABOUT THAT PART
UNTIL YOU'RE UNDER WAY.
CENTURIES AGO,
A SET OF KATRIC ARKS
WERE DISCOVERED
AT THE P'JEM MONASTERY.
KATRIC ARKS?
POLYCRYSTALLINE VESSELS,
ALLEGEDLY USED BY ANCIENT
VULCANS TO PRESERVE KATRAS.
THEY WERE SCANNED,
ANALYZED.
ONE OF THE SCIENTISTS EVEN
ATTEMPTED TO MELD WITH THEM.
THEY FOUND NOTHING TO INDICATE
THE PRESENCE OF A KATRA.
THE VULCAN SCIENCE ACADEMY
WAS JUST AS SKEPTICAL
ABOUT TIME TRAVEL.
DO YOU REALLY BELIEVE
YOU POSSESS THE LIVING SPIRIT
OF SURAK INSIDE YOU,
A MAN WHO DIED
1,800 YEARS AGO?
NOT WHEN YOU
PUT IT LIKE THAT.
THERE IS A LOGICAL
EXPLANATION.
I'M LISTENING.
SYRRAN MELDED WITH YOU
BEFORE HE DIED.
WHAT YOU'RE EXPERIENCING
IS THE RESIDUE OF HIS THOUGHTS.
SO I'M SUFFERING
FROM A MIND-MELD HANGOVER?
I WOULDN'T CHARACTERIZE IT
QUITE THAT WAY...
BUT, ESSENTIALLY.
IT FEELS LIKE...
...MORE THAN THAT.
YOU HAVE NO BASIS
FOR COMPARISON.
YOU'VE NEVER UNDERGONE
A MIND-MELD BEFORE.
SEEING SURAK
IS ONLY A PART OF IT.
I COULD SWEAR I'VE BEEN HERE
BEFORE, IN THIS SANCTUARY.
IT'S LIKE COMING BACK
TO THE HOUSE YOU GREW UP IN.
SYRRAN SPENT
A GREAT DEAL OF TIME HERE.
LET'S SAY YOU'RE RIGHT,
AND IT WAS JUST A MIND-MELD.
HE STILL PUT SOMETHING
IN MY HEAD...
...AND I WANT IT TAKEN OUT.
IT MAY NOT BE POSSIBLE.
WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU?
WHERE IS YOUR CAPTAIN?
HE'S INDISPOSED AT THE MOMENT.
CAN I HELP YOU?
THE INVESTIGATION
OF THE EMBASSY BOMBING
IS NEARLY COMPLETE.
YOU HAVE A SUSPECT?
THE EVIDENCE AGAINST HIM
AND THE SYRRANNITES
IS COMPELLING.
THERE'S NO LONGER ANY NEED
FOR YOUR PRESENCE HERE.
IF IT'S ALL THE SAME TO YOU,
WE'D LIKE TO STICK AROUND.
WE'D PREFER YOU DIDN'T.
THIS IS AN INTERNAL MATTER.
WE'LL KEEP STARFLEET APPRISED
IF THERE ARE
ANY SUBSEQUENT DEVELOPMENTS.
EXCELLENCY --
AGAIN, YOU HAVE MY DEEPEST
SYMPATHY FOR YOUR LOSS.
ALL OF VULCAN GRIEVES WITH YOU.
WITH ALL RESPECT,
WE AREN'T LEAVING,
NOT UNTIL WE KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
I'VE ALSO CONTACTED
ADMIRAL GARDNER.
I'M SURE YOU'LL BE HEARING
FROM HIM SOON.
-A PLEASANT JOURNEY.
-[ BEEPS ]
THE SON OF A BITCH
HUNG UP ON US.
SHOULD I TRY TO GET HIM BACK?
NO ONE HERE HAS EVER PERFORMED
THIS RITUAL.
I'VE STUDIED IT FOR SOME TIME.
I BELIEVE I CAN CONDUCT IT
SUCCESSFULLY.
YOU'D NOT ONLY BE PLACING
SURAK'S KATRA IN JEOPARDY --
YOU COULD KILL ARCHER.
THE RISKS ARE ACCEPTABLE.
I DOUBT SURAK WOULD AGREE.
WHAT ALTERNATIVE
WOULD YOU SUGGEST --
THAT WE FOLLOW THIS HUMAN?
I BELIEVE
YOUR PREJUDICE TOWARDS HUMANS
IS CLOUDING YOUR JUDGMENT.
YOU QUESTIONING MY LOGIC?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
Syrran chose to place the katra
in Archer.
He must have had his reasons,
even if we don't understand
them.
The reason is obvious.
He was dying.
Your daughter couldn't reach him
in time.
He had to choose Archer.
That may be.
But we do have a choice.
Now, for the sake
of everyone involved,
I ask you to reconsider.
I've made my decision.
I'll perform the procedure
in one hour.
And if Archer dies?
I won't sacrifice our future to
protect the life of one human.
YOU KNOW...
...I'M THE ONE
WITH A VULCAN GHOST IN HIS HEAD,
DEPENDING ON WHO YOU BELIEVE.
BUT...I DON'T FEEL
HALF AS BAD AS YOU LOOK.
I'M CONSIDERING OUR OPTIONS.
AT LEAST WE KNOW
YOUR MOTHER'S OKAY.
SHE'S JOINED A VIOLENT CULT.
SHE'S NOT OKAY.
I DON'T THINK THESE PEOPLE HAD
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE EMBASSY.
YOU SOUND CONVINCED.
LET'S JUST SAY
IT'S MORE THAN A GUT FEELING.
[ DOOR CREAKS OPEN ]
WE'VE COME TO A DECISION.
THE KATRA MUST BE REMOVED.
I CAN'T ARGUE WITH THAT.
THERE'S A PROCEDURE, A RITUAL.
IT WILL TRANSFER
THE KATRA TO ANOTHER PERSON.
IT'S NOT WITHOUT RISK.
VULCAN NEUROLOGY
IS EXCEPTIONALLY RESILIENT,
BUT A HUMAN'S...
THE SHOCK TO YOUR
NERVOUS SYSTEM WILL BE SEVERE.
IT COULD KILL YOU.
YOU MUST DECLINE.
WE'RE NOT OFFERING A CHOICE.
YOU'D DO THIS BY FORCE?
WE'D PREFER THAT YOU UNDERTAKE
THE RITUAL WILLINGLY.
IT WILL STAND
A BETTER CHANCE OF SUCCESS.
HOWEVER, IF FORCE IS REQUIRED,
WE WON'T HESITATE TO USE IT.
LET'S GET STARTED.
CAPTAIN.
IT'S MY CALL.
ADMIRAL GARDNER FOLLOWED
THE VULCAN LINE
STRAIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
HE WANTS US OUT OF HERE
YESTERDAY.
DID YOU TELL HIM
ABOUT THE CAPTAIN AND T'POL?
I LEFT THAT PART OUT.
ENTERPRISE WAS SUPPOSED
TO LEAVE ORBIT AN HOUR AGO.
V'LAS IS NOT A PATIENT MAN.
THERE'S NOT A WHOLE LOT
HE CAN DO ABOUT IT.
-HELL OF A JOB, TRAVIS.
-THANK YOU, SIR.
JUST FIND THEM
AND BRING THEM BACK --
-NO SIGHTSEEING ALONG THE WAY.
-UNDERSTOOD.
WE'VE GOT A RECON SATELLITE
TO JAM.
Enterprise hasn't left orbit.
They're maintaining a stationary
position above The Forge.
[ SIGHS ]
KEEP MONITORING THEM.
-Yes, Excellency.
-[ BEEPING ]
WE CAN'T PROCEED
WITH THE OPERATION
WHILE THE EARTH SHIP IS THERE.
YOU'RE CONCERNED
ABOUT WITNESSES.
GARDNER GAVE THEM
AN ORDER TO LEAVE.
I HEARD THE TRANSMISSION.
SO NOW WE'RE MONITORING
THEIR COMMUNICATIONS?
THEY WOULDN'T DISOBEY AN ORDER
WITHOUT A REASON.
I INTEND TO FIND OUT WHAT IT IS.
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
PASSED DOWN THROUGH THE AGES,
THE KATRA OF SURAK...
FATHER OF ALL WE HOLD TRUE,
LIVES ON IN THIS MAN.
LET IT NOW...LIVE ON IN ME.
[ SPEAKING VULCAN ]
SURAK.
[ GRUNTING ]
GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
MY APPEARANCE MUST BE
QUITE DISCONCERTING.
I APOLOGIZE.
RADIATION SICKNESS?
WE'RE PAYING A HEAVY PRICE
FOR OUR FOOLISHNESS.
LOGIC HAS NOT WON THIS DAY...
BUT THIS DAY WON'T LAST FOREVER.
LOGIC IS AT THE HEART
OF EVERY VULCAN.
EVEN AS THE ASHES FALL,
MY PEOPLE ARE DISCOVERING
A NEW WAY.
YOU CAN ACCOMPLISH
WHAT SYRRAN COULD NOT.
BUT SYRRAN...
WAS A VULCAN.
AND YOU'RE HUMAN...
WHICH MEANS
YOU ARE UNTOUCHED BY A CULTURE
THAT CAN NO LONGER SEE
ITS OWN IMMINENT DESTRUCTION.
I CANNOT LET WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE VULCANS OF MY TIME
TAKE PLACE AGAIN.
FIND WHAT MY PEOPLE HAVE LOST.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GROANING ]
FIND THE KIR'SHARA.
[ GASPING ]
CAPTAIN.
I FAILED.
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
SURAK CHOOSES
TO REMAIN WHERE HE IS.
-THE SATELLITE'S BEEN DISABLED.
-[ BEEPING ]
THEY'VE GOT 6 MINUTES
TO GET THROUGH.
TRAVIS...IT'S ALL YOURS.
PROBABLY SHOULD HAVE SKIPPED
BREAKFAST THIS MORNING.
[ BEEPING ]
-THEY'RE THROUGH.
-WE'RE LOSING CONTACT.
THESE THERMALS
ARE ONLY GOING TO GET STRONGER.
[ THUDDING ]
THAT WAS NO THERMAL.
[ GRUNTS ]
THE PLASMA CANNONS
ARE STILL WORKING,
BUT I CAN'T SAY THE SAME
FOR THE TARGETING SENSORS.
WE MUST BE GETTING CLOSE
TO THE GEOMAGNETIC FIELD.
IT DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE AFFECTING THEM.
THEY MUST HAVE
BETTER SHIELDING.
I'LL HAVE TO AIM MANUALLY.
CAN YOU GET US ON THEIR TAIL?
[ GRUNTING ]
HOW ARE THEY STILL BELOW US?
WE'VE LOST
PART OF THE STARBOARD WING.
-WE HAVE TO ABORT.
-I THINK I CAN GET US DOWN.
YOU WON'T BE ABLE
TO GET US BACK UP.
-[ BEEPING ]
-THRUSTERS ARE OFF-LINE.
WE'LL HAVE TO FIRE
THE CHEMICAL ROCKETS. HANG ON.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY'VE BEEN FIRED ON.
THEY TOOK DAMAGE, BUT THEY'RE
HEADING BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
I GUESS 6 MINUTES
WASN'T ENOUGH.
THEY MUST
HAVE BEEN MONITORING US.
THREE SHIPS CLOSING
ON OUR POSITION.
[ BEEPING ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
IT'S ADMINISTRATOR V'LAS.
WHY DID YOU LAUNCH
A SHUTTLEPOD?
WHY THE HELL
DID YOU FIRE ON IT?
YOU HAD NO AUTHORIZATION.
ANSWER THE QUESTION.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR OUR CAPTAIN.
ARCHER'S ON THE SURFACE?
HE'S IN THE FORGE,
SEARCHING FOR THE SYRRANNITES.
YOU WERE ORDERED
TO LEAVE ORBIT.
I ADVISED THEM TO STAY.
I ASSUME YOU ASSISTED
IN DISABLING
THE SECURITY SATELLITE.
I GAVE THEM THE CODE.
COMMANDER TUCKER...
YOU'RE TO BREAK ORBIT
IMMEDIATELY.
WE'RE NOT LEAVING
WITHOUT THE CAPTAIN.
YOU WILL LEAVE IMMEDIATELY
OR I'LL ORDER MY SHIPS
TO OPEN FIRE.
HOW IS HE?
HIS BREATHING HAS STABILIZED...
BUT HIS FEVER IS STILL HIGH.
HE AGREED TO THE RITUAL.
IF HE HADN'T,
YOU WOULD HAVE FORCED HIM.
YOU CLAIM THAT SURAK'S TEACHINGS
HAVE BEEN CORRUPTED
BY THE HIGH COMMAND...
...BUT YOU'RE NO DIFFERENT.
THERE IS
A PROFOUND DIFFERENCE.
YOU DECEIVE YOURSELF.
T'POL.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE COME HERE
LOOKING FOR YOU.
AND I DON'T WANT
ANYTHING MORE TO DO WITH YOU.
IF THAT'S YOUR WISH.
HOW LONG HAVE I BEEN OUT?
MORE THAN 3 HOURS.
I FEEL LIKE
I JUST PULLED MY HEAD
OUT OF A PLASMA RELAY.
YOU SHOULD REST.
[ SIGHING ]
THE KIR'SHARA.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT IT?
IT WAS IMPORTANT TO SURAK.
AND IT'S IN THERE.
WHAT'S A KIR'SHARA?
AN ARTIFACT --
SYRRAN LED US HERE TO FIND IT.
IF HE KNOWS WHERE IT IS...
TELESCOPES HAVE SIGHTED
THREE VULCAN CRUISERS
IN ORBIT OVER THE FORGE.
THE HIGH COMMAND KNOWS
WE'RE HERE.
WE SHOULD EVACUATE
IMMEDIATELY.
GIVE THE ORDER.
I CAN FIND IT.
[ RUMBLING, BEEPING ]
THAT ONE MISSED US
BY 20 METERS.
TACTICAL ALERT.
POLARIZE HULL PLATING.
HOW MANY WARNING SHOTS
DO VULCANS USUALLY FIRE?
NONE.
[ BEEPING ]
V'LAS.
I'M RUNNING OUT OF PATIENCE,
COMMANDER.
WE'VE BEEN OVER THIS.
OUR CAPTAIN AND FIRST OFFICER
ARE DOWN THERE.
WE'LL MAKE SURE
THEY'RE RETURNED TO YOU.
BREAK ORBIT -- NOW.
[ BEEPS ]
YOU REALLY THINK HE'LL DO IT?
V'LAS WILL DO WHATEVER IT TAKES
TO ACCOMPLISH HIS GOAL.
VULCAN AND EARTH HAVE BEEN
ALLIES FOR A HUNDRED YEARS.
SYRRANNITES MUST HAVE SEEN
OUR SHIPS BY NOW.
IF THEY EVACUATE INTO THE FORGE,
THEY'LL BE
EXTREMELY HARD TO TRACK.
WE CAN'T WAIT ANY LONGER.
[ BEEPING ]
DRIVE ENTERPRISE FROM ORBIT.
USE ALL NECESSARY FORCE.
Yes, Excellency.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
PHASE CANNONS, RETURN FIRE.
THE VULCAN SHIPS
ARE FIRING ON ENTERPRISE.
-WE COULD BE NEXT.
-[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
TAKE CHARGE OF THE EVACUATION.
WE'LL MEET YOU ON THE FORGE
AS SOON AS WE CAN.
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE.
I'VE SPENT TWO YEARS
SEARCHING FOR THE ARTIFACT.
IF THERE'S A CHANCE
OF FINDING IT...
T'POL?
I'M STAYING.
GO.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
-[ ALARM BLARING ]
-[ GRUNTS ]
RE-ROUTE EMERGENCY POWER
TO PHASE CANNONS.
HULL BREACH ON C-DECK.
THEY'RE REPORTING CASUALTIES.
-[ BEEPING ]
-V'LAS IS HAILING, AUDIO ONLY.
PUT HIM THROUGH.
[ BEEPING ]
You're hopelessly outgunned.
Weapons are off-line,
engines failing.
Don't force me
to destroy your ship.
[ BEEPS ]
HE'S RIGHT.
WE SHOULD WITHDRAW.
OUR DEATHS WON'T HELP
CAPTAIN ARCHER OR T'POL.
GET US THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
THE MOMENT ENTERPRISE
IS BEYOND SCANNER RANGE,
BEGIN BOMBARDMENT
OF THE COMPOUND.
Yes, Excellency.
[ BEEPING ]
T'KLAAS --
HE WAS A STUDENT OF SURAK, ONE
OF THE FIRST KOLINAHR MASTERS.
THERE'S NO INSCRIPTION,
NOTHING TO INDICATE
HIS BLOODLINE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW HIS NAME?
WE'RE GETTING CLOSE.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
THEY'VE BEGUN THEIR ASSAULT.
IT'S HERE.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
I HAD MY DOUBTS
WHETHER IT REALLY EXISTED.
[ EXPLOSION ]
LET'S GO.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
THIS WAY.
REPORT.
Geomagnetic interference --
we can't get a target lock.
BLANKET THE AREA.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ ALL PANTING ]
The sanctuary's
been destroyed.
COMB THE DESERT.
MAKE SURE
THERE ARE NO SURVIVORS.
Affirmative.
YOU'RE PRESIDING OVER
A MASSACRE.
WE ARE ELIMINATING A THREAT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
WE SHOULD KEEP MOVING.
-[ GROANING ]
-CAPTAIN.
[ GROANING ]
I WAS AFRAID
YOU WERE STILL INSIDE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE FOUND THE KIR'SHARA.
YOU HAVE ALWAYS STRUGGLED SO
WITH YOUR EMOTIONS.
I CAME HERE...
I DID ALL THIS TO HELP YOU.
[ GROANS ]
[ Voice breaking ]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU WILL.
[ CRYING ]
MOTHER...
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN SO PROUD
OF YOU...MY T'POL.
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
MOTHER.
[ SNIFFLES ]
I UNDERSTAND
WE SUFFERED CASUALTIES.
INJURIES, TWO OF THEM SERIOUS.
I SHARE YOUR CONCERN
ABOUT CAPTAIN ARCHER AND T'POL.
THEY'VE BEEN IN TOUGH JAMS
BEFORE.
WHAT DOES THE HIGH COMMAND HAVE
AGAINST THE SYRRANNITES?
THEY WENT TO A LOT OF TROUBLE
TO FRAME THEM
FOR THE EMBASSY BOMBING.
THE SYRRANNITES
BELIEVE VIOLENCE
TO BE ANTITHETICAL
TO SURAK'S TEACHINGS.
SO THEY'RE PACIFISTS.
V'LAS CONSIDERS THAT
A DANGEROUS MIND-SET,
PARTICULARLY NOW.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THE HIGH COMMAND IS PLANNING
TO ATTACK ANDORIA.
WAIT. WAIT.
VULCAN AND ANDORIA SIGNED
A PEACE TREATY TWO YEARS AGO.
CAPTAIN ARCHER
HELPED NEGOTIATE IT.
VULCAN INTELLIGENCE CLAIMS
THE ANDORIANS
ARE DEVELOPING A WEAPON,
POSSIBLY BASED
ON XINDI TECHNOLOGY.
AND YOU DON'T BELIEVE IT.
I SUSPECT V'LAS IS USING
THE CLAIM TO ADVANCE AN AGENDA.
HE'S PERSUADED THE HIGH COMMAND
TO LAUNCH A PREEMPTIVE STRIKE.
HE'S GONNA START
AN INTERSTELLAR WAR.
ONE THAT COULD DEVASTATE
ANDORIA AND VULCAN,
AND EVENTUALLY INVOLVE
OTHER WORLDS...
INCLUDING EARTH.
SET A COURSE FOR ANDORIA.
ANDORIA?
MAXIMUM WARP.