I ADMIT IT.
I'VE GOT A FEW BUTTERFLIES.
OKAY, MORE THAN A FEW.
YOU HAVEN'T STOPPED TALKING
ABOUT THIS FOR A WEEK.
IT'S DIFFERENT FOR YOU.
YOU GREW UP WITH THE MAN.
WHEN I WAS 7, MY MOM
BOUGHT ME A BOOK ABOUT HIM.
"EMORY ERICKSON:
FATHER OF THE TRANSPORTER."
I MADE HER READ IT TO ME
EVERY NIGHT FOR A MONTH.
THAT BOOK IS THE REASON
I BECAME AN ENGINEER.
DID I EVER TELL YOU ABOUT
MEETING ZEFRAM COCHRANE?
YEAH, ONLY ABOUT 50 TIMES.
THEN YOU KNOW I UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU FEEL.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU WANT A MIRROR?
YOU'VE GOT A MEAN STREAK IN YOU,
YOU KNOW THAT?
[ CONTROL KEYS CLACKING ]
[ SIGHS ]
NOTHING SEEMS TO BE MISSING.
HELLO, EMORY.
JONATHAN, LOOK AT YOU.
I ALWAYS
SUSPECTED YOU'D BE FAMOUS.
JUST DIDN'T THINK THAT YOU'D BE
MORE FAMOUS THAN ME!
-JON.
-GOOD TO SEE YOU.
OH, WE HAVE A LOT
OF CATCHING UP TO DO.
DO IT LATER.
I WANT A TOUR OF THIS PLACE.
MY CHIEF ENGINEER,
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER.
IT'S AN HONOR.
GUESS YOU AND I WILL BE SPENDING
SOME TIME TOGETHER.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO IT.
DANICA. TRIP.
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND THAT I'M
BORROWING YOUR SHIP, CAPTAIN.
AS LONG AS YOU RETURN IT
IN GOOD CONDITION.
DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN PROMISE THAT.
WHEN THIS TEST IS OVER,
ENTERPRISE AND ALL OF STARFLEET
COULD BE OBSOLETE.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE TRYING TO
PUT ME OUT OF A JOB.
[ LAUGHS ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
IN PREPARATION FOR
DR. ERICKSON'S EXPERIMENT,
WE'VE REDUCED POWER IN ALL
BUT ESSENTIAL AREAS OF THE SHIP.
FEEL LIKE SOME COMPANY?
WE HAVEN'T TALKED
MUCH SINCE VULCAN.
HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
I'M FINE.
I'VE BEEN SEEING
YOU BY YOURSELF A LOT.
I'M READING THE KIR'SHARA.
HOW IS IT?
INTERESTING.
INTERESTING?
EXTREMELY.
LOOK, I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH.
LOSING A FAMILY MEMBER, IT'S
THE TOUGHEST THING THERE IS.
I SEE NO POINT IN DISCUSSING IT.
IT'S IN THE PAST.
YOUR MOTHER DIED A WEEK AGO.
TALKING WON'T CHANGE THAT.
IT MAY CHANGE
THE WAY YOU FEEL ABOUT IT.
I DON'T FEEL ANYTHING
ABOUT IT.
WELL,
YOU CAN TELL YOURSELF THAT.
IT'S THE TRUTH.
YOU KNOW, WHEN LIZZIE DIED,
THERE WERE TIMES
I WANTED TO JUST CLOSE UP
AND RETREAT INSIDE OF MYSELF.
TRIP, I APPRECIATE
WHAT YOU'RE TRYING TO DO,
BUT IT'S NOT NECESSARY.
YOU'RE FINE?
WELL...
IF YOU EVER DO WANT TO TALK,
LET ME KNOW.
I'LL SEE YOU.
SUB-QUANTUM TELEPORTATION.
YOU STEP ONTO A TRANSPORTER
ON EARTH,
A FEW SECONDS LATER,
YOU'RE ON VULCAN.
THAT'S OVER 16 LIGHT-YEARS.
THAT'S JUST FOR STARTERS.
THEORETICALLY, THERE IS NO LIMIT
TO THE DISTANCE.
ONE OF THE THINGS
WE'RE HERE TO TEST.
YOU TELL ME,
WITH THAT KIND OF TECHNOLOGY,
WHO'D HAVE ANY USE
FOR A STARSHIP?
MAYBE YOU WILL
PUT ME OUT OF A JOB.
DAD.
I WOULDN'T WORRY TOO MUCH.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE DECADES
TO WORK OUT ALL THE BUGS.
BUT WHEN WE DO,
STARFLEET'S GOING TO LOOK
A HELL OF A LOT DIFFERENT.
THAT'S IF IT EXISTS AT ALL.
YOU CAN SEE HE HASN'T CHANGED.
I REMEMBER YOU AND MY FATHER
HAVING SIMILAR DISCUSSIONS.
HE BELIEVED THE FUTURE
WAS IN THE WARP DRIVE.
I BELIEVED
IN THE TRANSPORTER PAD.
I MISS THOSE TALKS.
I MISS HIM.
TO HENRY.
THE VULCAN SCIENCE ACADEMY
HAS BEEN STUDYING SUB-QUANTUM
TRANSPORTING FOR SOME TIME
WITH LITTLE RESULT.
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO GET MY HANDS
ON SOME OF THAT RESEARCH
FOR YEARS.
IN HINDSIGHT, IT'S PROBABLY JUST
AS WELL THAT I COULDN'T.
MIGHT HAVE SENT ME
DOWN THE WRONG PATH.
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE --
BEAMING SOMEONE THAT FAR.
ALL BREAKTHROUGHS ARE HARD
TO IMAGINE BEFORE THEY HAPPEN.
WHEN I DEVELOPED
THE TRANSPORTER,
MOST PEOPLE SIMPLY
COULDN'T GRASP IT.
SOME STILL CAN'T.
I HAVE TO CONFESS,
GIVEN A CHOICE,
I'D MUCH RATHER USE A GOOD
OLD-FASHIONED SHUTTLEPOD.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'LL NEVER FORGET THE PROTESTS
WHEN THE TRANSPORTER WAS FIRST
APPROVED FOR BIO-MATTER.
OH, GOD, HERE WE GO.
PEOPLE SAID IT WAS UNSAFE,
THAT IT CAUSED
BRAIN CANCER, PSYCHOSIS,
AND EVEN SLEEP DISORDERS.
AND THEN THERE WAS ALL
THAT METAPHYSICAL CHATTER
ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT THE PERSON
WHO ARRIVED AFTER THE TRANSPORT
WAS THE SAME PERSON WHO LEFT,
AND NOT SOME WEIRD COPY.
WHICH WOULD MAKE
ALL OF US COPIES.
I HAD TO FIGHT ALL
OF THAT NONSENSE.
AND I'M NOT GONNA TELL YOU
THERE WEREN'T COSTS.
I'M LIVING PROOF OF THAT,
BUT I WON.
MANKIND IS BETTER OFF.
MAKES EVERYTHING I FOUGHT FOR
WORTHWHILE.
HERE'S TO
A SUCCESSFUL EXPERIMENT.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'RE ENTERING AN AREA
KNOWN AS THE BARRENS.
THERE'S NOT A STAR SYSTEM
WITHIN 100 LIGHT-YEARS.
PERFECT CONDITIONS
FOR EMORY'S TEST.
THOSE EARLY DAYS
WERE PRETTY TERRIFYING.
I'M LUCKY TO BE ALIVE.
IS IT TRUE YOU WERE THE FIRST
PERSON TO GO THROUGH?
I WASN'T ABOUT TO LET
ANYONE ELSE DO IT.
YOU MUST HAVE BEEN SCARED.
TERRIFIED.
THAT ORIGINAL TRANSPORTER
TOOK A FULL MINUTE AND A HALF
TO CYCLE THROUGH.
FELT LIKE A YEAR.
YOU COULD ACTUALLY FEEL YOURSELF
BEING TAKEN APART
AND PUT BACK TOGETHER.
WHEN I MATERIALIZED, FIRST THING
I DID WAS LOSE MY LUNCH.
SECOND THING I DID
WAS GET STONE DRUNK.
TRICK I LEARNED
FROM ZEFRAM COCHRANE.
NOW, THERE WAS A MAN
WHO KNEW THE BENEFITS
OF A LITTLE LIQUID COURAGE.
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
WELL, YOU'RE GONNA NEED
MORE JUICE THAN I THOUGHT.
NOT MORE THAN
ENTERPRISE CAN SPARE.
WELL... WE'LL HAVE TO DRAW
DIRECTLY FROM THE WARP REACTOR.
MAY EVEN HAVE TO
SHUT DOWN A FEW SYSTEMS.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO
LEAVE THE LIGHTS ON.
YEAH.
IF I COULD GET A LOOK
AT YOUR POWER CONVERTER,
-IT MIGHT HELP ME OUT.
-I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
WHEN I'M DONE WITH THIS,
I'LL INSTALL THE CONVERTER.
SEE IF I CAN'T MAKE
LIFE EASIER ON YOU.
WELL, THANKS,
BUT WHEN IT COMES TO
MODIFYING OUR SYSTEMS,
I PREFER TO DO THINGS MYSELF.
CAN I GET A LOOK AT IT?
I SAID I'D INSTALL
THE CONVERTER.
AND I SAID "NO, THANKS."
I WISH I HAD TIME TO DEBATE
THE FINER POINTS
OF ENGINEERING PROTOCOL,
BUT AS YOU CAN SEE,
I'M EXTREMELY BUSY.
AND I REALIZE THIS IS YOUR SHIP
AND I'M ONLY A GUEST.
BUT LET ME REMIND YOU
THAT STARFLEET HAS GRANTED ME
COMPLETE ACCESS
TO YOUR SYSTEMS.
IF YOU HADN'T NOTICED,
I'M MORE THAN CAPABLE
OF HANDLING
A LITTLE POWER UPGRADE.
HAND ME THAT, WILL YOU?
THAT'S THE MAIN REACTOR
AND THOSE ARE
THE PLASMA FEEDS, RIGHT?
YOU KNOW THE SHIP
LIKE A MEMBER OF THE CREW.
I'VE READ JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING
I COULD FIND ON HER.
I PROBABLY COULD DESCRIBE
EVERY ONE OF YOUR MISSIONS.
STILL WONDER WHY
YOU HAVEN'T SIGNED ON.
I THINK YOU KNOW THE ANSWER.
YOUR FATHER SEEMS LIKE HE CAN
TAKE CARE OF HIMSELF.
HE SURE HASN'T
LOST ANY OF HIS EDGE.
CAN'T ARGUE WITH THAT.
SO, WHY ARE YOU STILL ON EARTH?
HE NEEDS ME.
HE STILL HASN'T
GOTTEN OVER QUINN.
IT'S BEEN 14 YEARS.
FIFTEEN.
HE LOST A SON.
IF YOU LEAVE,
HE'LL LOSE A DAUGHTER.
IF THIS TEST GOES WELL,
IT'LL BE A NEW START FOR HIM.
GIVE HIM SOMETHING
TO LOOK FORWARD TO.
HE WON'T SPEND ALL OF HIS TIME
THINKING ABOUT THE PAST.
AND IF THE TEST
DOESN'T GO WELL?
I DON'T KNOW.
WE BOTH GREW UP WITH FATHERS
WHO COULD BE PRETTY DEMANDING.
THAT'S AN UNDERSTATEMENT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
MAYBE YOU SHOULD START THINKING
MORE ABOUT YOURSELF.
I KNOW,
IT'S HARD TAKING ADVICE
FROM SOMEONE WHO USED TO
CHASE YOU AROUND THE BACKYARD
WITH A PLASTIC LASER PISTOL.
YEAH, BUT IT'S GOOD ADVICE,
JONATHAN.
I JUST WISH I COULD FOLLOW IT.
HOW WAS YOUR TOUR?
I ENJOYED IT.
I CAN ALWAYS TELL
WHEN YOU'RE UPSET.
YOU DO THIS LIKE
YOU'RE IN A HURRY.
DON'T YOU THINK THERE'S
SOMETHING TO BE UPSET ABOUT?
WE'RE HERE.
THAT'S REASON
ENOUGH TO BE OPTIMISTIC.
-WE'RE LYING TO THEM.
-WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
WE COULD TALK TO JON.
HE MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP US.
NO. HE WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
WE CAN'T SAY ANYTHING TO HIM.
WE CAN'T TRUST ANYONE.
IT'S JON.
HE'S A STARFLEET CAPTAIN.
HIS FIRST DUTY IS TO HIS SHIP.
YOU TALK ABOUT HIM
LIKE HE'S AN ENEMY.
HE'S NOT AN ENEMY.
BUT HE'S NOT ON OUR SIDE,
EITHER. BELIEVE ME.
IT'S FROM OVER THERE.
NO.
I'LL TAKE UP.
YOU TAKE DOWN.
IT COULD BE A FORM
OF SPATIAL DISTORTION.
CAN YOU PINPOINT IT?
F-DECK. NEAR THE ARMORY.
[ CRACKLING ]
AAAAH!
SICKBAY!
CREWMAN DOWN IN THE ARMORY!
HE SUFFERED MASSIVE
CELLULAR DISRUPTION,
AS IF HE'D BEEN SUBJECTED
TO INTENSE DELTA RADIATION.
DID OTHER CREWMEN
SEE ANYTHING?
THE LIGHTS
WERE MALFUNCTIONING.
THIS ANOMALY YOU DETECTED --
YOU THINK IT WAS
SOMEHOW RESPONSIBLE?
IT SHOWED UP
AT THE SAME TIME...
IN THE SAME LOCATION.
CAN'T HAVE BEEN A COINCIDENCE.
I SYMPATHIZE, BELIEVE ME.
DURING THE INITIAL TESTS
FOR THE TRANSPORTER,
SOME BRAVE MEN
AND WOMEN WERE LOST.
NOT A DAY GOES BY
THAT I DON'T THINK ABOUT THEM.
HOW CAN I HELP?
YOU'VE SPENT A GREAT DEAL
OF TIME IN THIS REGION OF SPACE.
I NEVER ENCOUNTERED
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
ARE YOU SURE?
THERE'S A REASON THIS IS CALLED
THE BARRENS, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NOTHING OUT HERE.
SOMETHING OUT HERE
KILLED ONE OF MY CREWMEN.
I WISH I HAD
AN EXPLANATION FOR YOU.
[ GROANS ]
WHAT IS IT?
TIME FOR MY TREATMENT.
DANI.
I'M SORRY.
CAN WE, UH,
CONTINUE THIS LATER?
OF COURSE.
CALM DOWN.
YOU NEVER SAID ANYTHING
LIKE THIS WOULD HAPPEN!
I DIDN'T KNOW THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
DAD...
A MAN IS DEAD.
AND WE'RE RESPONSIBLE.
I'M NOT GOING TO GO ALONG
WITH THIS ANYMORE.
-LISTEN TO ME.
-NO.
NO. WE'VE GOT TO
TELL THEM THE TRUTH.
DANI, YOU'RE CONDEMNING HIM
TO DEATH!
I'M CONDEMNING HIM?
HOW DO YOU KNOW
HE ISN'T ALREADY DEAD?
HE'S ALIVE.
DAD...
JONATHAN'S PRACTICALLY
FAMILY.
HE AND QUINN
WERE BEST FRIENDS.
I KNOW. I KNOW THAT.
WE CAN'T DO THIS TO HIM,
TO HIS CREW.
WE'RE ALMOST READY
FOR OUR FIRST TEST.
SOMEONE ELSE
COULD DIE BEFORE THEN.
OH, THE ODDS OF THAT HAPPENING
AGAIN ARE EXTREMELY SMALL.
NO ONE'S GOING TO DIE.
I JUST NEED A COUPLE DAYS.
WE OWE HIM THAT MUCH, DANI.
I WONDER WHAT HE WOULD HAVE
TO SAY ABOUT ALL THIS...
ABOUT WHAT WE'RE DOING.
WHEN WE'RE DONE,
YOU CAN ASK HIM.
ROUTING POWER.
READY.
HELP ME UP.
-SIR?
-GIVE ME A HAND, PLEASE.
THIS PART I LIKE DOING MYSELF.
ENERGIZING.
[ BEEPING ]
THE PROBE MATERIALIZED
AT THE TARGET COORDINATES.
LOOKS LIKE IT
ARRIVED IN GOOD CONDITION.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE RECEIVING TELEMETRY.
We're already
getting back data.
Congratulations, Emory.
40,000 KILOMETERS.
NOTHING'S EVER GONE THAT FAR.
IT'S A START.
IT'S GONNA TAKE A FEW HOURS
TO GATHER ALL THE TELEMETRY.
LET'S CELEBRATE IN MESS HALL.
MY TREAT.
I LIKE TO MONITOR
THE DATA AS IT COMES IN.
I'M SORT OF OBSESSIVE
THAT WAY.
THEN LET ME BRING
SOMETHING BACK FOR YOU.
HELP PASS THE TIME
BETWEEN DATA-STREAMS.
NO, THANKS.
IT'S BEEN A LONG DAY.
YOU MUST BE STARVING.
YOU GO AHEAD.
I'LL JOIN YOU LATER.
SURE YOU DON'T WANT
A SECOND PAIR OF EYES?
ONE PAIR WILL DO.
AND NO OFFENSE, COMMANDER,
BUT I WORK MUCH BETTER
WHEN I'M NOT BEING DISTRACTED.
YOU KNOW WHERE TO FIND ME.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
MOST OF THE WORK
EMORY HAD ME DO --
TAPPING INTO THE WARP REACTOR
FOR EXTRA POWER,
REROUTING THE PLASMA FLOW --
IT WASN'T NECESSARY
FOR THE TEST.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
-REMEMBER WHEN
THE LIGHTS DIMMED?
-YEAH.
WELL, HE CHANNELED THAT ENERGY
INTO A FEEDBACK LOOP.
IT WASN'T GOING INTO THE BEAM.
MAYBE HE NEEDS THE POWER
FOR ANOTHER PHASE
OF THE EXPERIMENT.
WELL, FROM WHAT I CAN TELL,
HIS SUB-QUANTUM
VERSION SHOULD USE
LESS ENERGY
THAN A REGULAR TRANSPORTER.
THAT'S ONE OF THE REASONS
IT'S SO BRILLIANT.
EITHER HE WAS KEEPING ME BUSY,
MAKING SURE I WAS
LOOKING THE OTHER WAY,
OR THIS SUB-QUANTUM THING
IS A SMOKESCREEN
FOR SOMETHING ELSE,
SOMETHING
HE HASN'T TOLD US ABOUT.
I WOULDN'T HAVE
PICKED UP ON ANY OF IT
IF YOU HADN'T ASKED ME
TO TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
WHEN I ASKED EMORY ABOUT
THE ANOMALY THAT KILLED BURROWS,
HE CLAIMED HE'D NEVER
HEARD OF ANYTHING LIKE IT.
NOT TRUE?
SOMETHING VERY SIMILAR APPEARED
ON EMORY'S RESEARCH SHIP...
5 YEARS AGO.
T'POL DUG UP THE REPORT
FROM STARFLEET'S DATA BANKS.
A CREW MEMBER SAW IT.
SAID IT SEEMED TO BE ALIVE.
-[ INTERCOM BEEPS ]
-Bridge to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
We're picking up another one.
IT'S ON C-DECK. SECTION 5.
On my way.
IT'S FLUCTUATING.
WHAT'S YOUR BEST GUESS?
I'VE LOST IT.
TAKE SECTION 3.
TAKE SECTION 4.
DON'T LET IT TOUCH YOU.
[ BEEPING ]
THIS WAY.
IT SHOULD BE HERE.
IT'S HIGHLY UNSTABLE,
SURROUNDED BY A SUBSPACE FIELD.
AAAAH!
[ GASPING ]
YOU'RE FORTUNATE YOU DIDN'T HAVE
MORE PROLONGED CONTACT.
CAN YOU PUT THAT
DOWN FOR 30 SECONDS?
I TOOK VISUAL READINGS.
CAN YOU SLOW IT DOWN?
HOLD IT.
ENHANCE.
A LITTLE MORE.
WHO IS IT?
IT'S QUINN.
EMORY'S SON.
THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
HE HASN'T AGED A DAY.
EMORY?
I'M NOT HERE TO
TEST A NEW TRANSPORTER.
I'M HERE TO BRING BACK MY SON.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WE WERE CONDUCTING
FIRST TRIALS.
MY GREATEST ACHIEVEMENT.
QUINN WANTED TO BE
THE FIRST TO GO THROUGH.
HE WAS A LOT LIKE HIS OLD MAN...
A LOT LIKE YOU.
I LOST HIS SIGNAL
AND COULDN'T GET IT BACK.
TRUTH IS,
THE SUB-QUANTUM TRANSPORTER
IS A FUNDAMENTALLY
FLAWED CONCEPT.
IT'LL NEVER WORK.
NOT NOW,
NOT A THOUSAND YEARS FROM NOW.
I SUPPOSE I KNEW THAT
AT THE TIME.
YOU LET HIM GO THROUGH
WITH THE TEST?
I WAS A RELATIVELY YOUNG MAN
WHO HAD CREATED SOMETHING
TO CHANGE STARFLEET.
AFTER AN ACHIEVEMENT
OF THAT MAGNITUDE,
THERE WAS
NOWHERE TO GO BUT DOWN.
MY LIFE BECAME
JUST ONE LONG STRUGGLE
TO RECAPTURE PAST GLORY.
I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT YOU.
I'M TALKING ABOUT QUINN.
I WASN'T THINKING
OF THE CONSEQUENCES.
YOU SAID YOU CAME
HERE TO GET HIM BACK?
THIS REGION, THE BARRENS,
IS ACTUALLY A SUBSPACE NODE --
A BUBBLE OF CURVED
SPACE-TIME.
IT'S WHY THERE ARE NO STARS.
QUINN'S TRANSPORTER SIGNAL
IS TRAPPED HERE.
AT CERTAIN INTERVALS,
THERE ARE FLUCTUATIONS
IN THE NODE
THAT CAUSE THE SIGNAL
TO REAPPEAR.
IF WE CAN LOCK ONTO IT
AT ONE OF THOSE INTERVALS,
WE CAN SAVE HIM.
YOU COULD HAVE TOLD ME
ALL OF THIS BEFORE.
STARFLEET WOULD NEVER HAVE
AUTHORIZED THE MISSION.
I HAD TO CREATE AN EXCUSE.
A MEMBER OF MY CREW IS DEAD.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT
THE MANIFESTATIONS
WOULD BE DANGEROUS, BELIEVE ME.
YOU WANT ME TO BELIEVE YOU?
I WANT YOU TO HELP ME.
QUINN WAS LIKE
A BROTHER TO YOU.
YOU WERE LIKE
MY SECOND FATHER.
YOU SHOULD HAVE TRUSTED ME.
ALL I NEED IS ONE MORE SCAN.
I CAN BRING HIM BACK.
-IS THAT THE TRUTH?
-I'M NOT LYING.
YOU'VE BEEN LYING TO ME
SINCE YOU CAME ABOARD.
I HAD NO CHOICE!
I'M SORRY.
PLEASE HELP ME, JONATHAN.
HELP ME SAVE MY SON.
PLEASE.
I WANT YOU BOTH
TO WORK WITH EMORY.
GIVE HIM
WHATEVER HELP HE NEEDS.
WHAT IS IT, TRIP?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M HEARING THIS.
-WE'VE ALREADY LOST ONE MAN.
-IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
WE'LL ALERT THE CREW
TO THE DANGER.
IF THEY'D BEEN ALERTED 24 HOURS
AGO, BURROWS MIGHT BE ALIVE.
WE DON'T FULLY UNDERSTAND
THE NATURE
OF THESE MANIFESTATIONS.
THEY COULD POSE OTHER DANGERS.
I KNOW THERE'S A RISK.
WE'RE TALKING ONE MORE DAY.
THAT'S ALL EMORY NEEDS.
-WHAT HE CLAIMS HE NEEDS.
-I BELIEVE HIM.
BECAUSE HE'S A FRIEND
OF THE FAMILY?
THAT'S NOT WHY I'M DOING THIS.
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
QUINN'S SIGNAL IS
GETTING WEAKER, TRIP.
IT'S BEEN DECAYING
FOR THE PAST 15 YEARS.
EMORY SAYS IF WE
DON'T DO SOMETHING NOW,
WE'LL NEVER GET HIM
BACK IN ONE PIECE.
WE HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
TO HELP.
WHAT ABOUT
EMORY'S RESPONSIBILITY?
HE LIED TO GET US OUT HERE.
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
BUT WE'RE HERE.
WE CAN'T JUST TURN THE SHIP
AROUND AND LEAVE A MAN TO DIE.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
I SUGGEST YOU GET STARTED.
WE'RE STILL GETTING
A SPIKE IN THE ARRAY.
I COULD SWAP OUT
THE EMITTER COILS
WITH SOMETHING
FROM ENGINEERING.
MIGHT EVEN OUT A BIT.
SOUNDS GOOD.
I'LL GET ON IT.
I KNOW YOU DON'T APPROVE
OF WHAT I'VE DONE.
YOU NEED MY APPROVAL?
I'M DISAPPOINTED
THAT YOU THINK LESS OF ME.
YOU LIKED ME BETTER
WHEN I WORSHIPED YOUR SHADOW?
YES.
IT'S AN HONEST ANSWER.
I'D THINK YOU'D BE
OUT OF PRACTICE.
YOU MAY WANT TO RESERVE JUDGMENT
ON MY ACTIONS
UNTIL YOU'VE LOST A SON.
I HAVE LOST SOMEONE CLOSE.
AND I'D DO ALMOST
ANYTHING TO GET HER BACK...
EXCEPT PUT OTHER PEOPLE
IN DANGER.
QUINN AND I USED TO
ARGUE ALL THE TIME.
WASN'T UNTIL I LOST HIM
THAT I REALIZED
THAT THOSE ARGUMENTS
WERE SOME OF THE HAPPIEST
MOMENTS OF MY LIFE.
[ SIGHS ]
I'LL BE IN ENGINEERING.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
[ WHINING ]
CAN I COME IN?
HEY, THERE.
YOU MUST BE PORTHOS.
HEARD A LOT ABOUT YOU.
HE'S GOT A LOT OF PERSONALITY.
AND AN APPETITE TO MATCH.
I WANTED TO SAY
THAT I'M SORRY.
I SHOULD HAVE
COME TO YOU EARLIER.
I FEEL RESPONSIBLE.
YOU LOST A CREWMAN.
WE CAN'T CHANGE WHAT'S HAPPENED.
MAYBE SOME GOOD
CAN COME OUT OF IT.
YOU THINK WE CAN GET HIM BACK?
I THINK THAT IT'S POSSIBLE.
THAT'S ENOUGH REASON
FOR ME TO TRY.
I WONDER...
WHAT IT MUST BE LIKE FOR HIM,
YOU KNOW.
IS HE IN PAIN?
IS HE CONSCIOUS?
IF HE IS, DOES HE THINK
THAT WE'VE FORGOTTEN ABOUT HIM?
QUINN WAS EVERYTHING
TO MY FATHER.
TO BOTH OF US.
GETTING HIM BACK IS ALL
THAT WE'VE THOUGHT ABOUT
FOR THE PAST 15 YEARS.
LET'S HOPE WHEN THIS IS OVER,
YOU'LL HAVE SOMETHING ELSE
TO THINK ABOUT.
THE POWER CONVERSION TABLES.
SOME OF THESE MODIFICATIONS
SHOULD HELP.
THANKS.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, I THINK
WE'RE PRETTY MUCH THERE.
I'M TRYING TO DECIDE
WHAT TO SHOW FOR MOVIE NIGHT.
MOVIE NIGHT?
YEAH, I THOUGHT
I'D FIRE UP THE OLD TRADITION.
YOU IN THE MOOD
FOR A HORROR FILM OR A MUSICAL?
I DON'T THINK I'LL HAVE THE TIME
FOR EITHER.
YOU CAN'T SPEND
EVERY SECOND OF YOUR LIFE
STUDYING THAT
WHATEVER IT'S CALLED.
-KIR'SHARA.
-YOU GOT TO TAKE
A BREAK EVENTUALLY.
EVENTUALLY.
I DON'T GET YOU, T'POL.
I THOUGHT YOU JOINED STARFLEET
SO YOU COULD INTERACT
A LITTLE MORE WITH HUMANS.
BUT IT SEEMS TO ME THAT
EVER SINCE WE LEFT SPACEDOCK,
YOU SPEND ALL YOUR FREE TIME
COOPED UP IN YOUR ROOM,
READING THAT BIBLE OF YOURS.
I MAY HAVE FOUND
NEW PRIORITIES.
WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
I'M NEEDED ON THE BRIDGE.
T'Pol to Captain Archer.
ARCHER.
I PICKED UP SOMETHING
THAT WAS IN YOUR AREA,
BUT I'VE LOST IT.
KEEP MONITORING.
HE'S HERE.
[ CRACKLING ]
[ BEEPING ]
JONATHAN. THERE.
QUINN?
[ CRASHING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ COUGHING ]
[ GASPING ]
IT KNOCKED OUT AN EPS JUNCTION.
REPAIR IS GOING TO
TAKE A COUPLE OF HOURS.
WILL IT AFFECT
THE TRANSPORTER?
NO.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE STILL
GOING THROUGH WITH IT --
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
THIS ARGUMENT AGAIN.
THAT THING BARELY MISSED
A STACK OF TORPEDOES.
IF IT HAD JUMPED
2 FEET TO THE LEFT,
WE WOULDN'T BE
HERE TO TALK ABOUT IT.
WE SHOULD CONCENTRATE
ON REPAIRING THE SHIP
SO WE CAN GET OUT OF HERE.
IF WE BEAM QUINN ABOARD,
THERE WON'T BE ANY MORE
OF THESE MANIFESTATIONS.
-HOW THE HELL DO YOU KNOW?
-TRIP!
YOU'RE PUTTING
YOUR PERSONAL FEELINGS
BEFORE THE SAFETY OF THE SHIP!
-AND YOU ARE THIS CLOSE
TO INSUBORDINATION!
-INSUBORDINATION?
I'VE MADE A DECISION.
IT'S THE RIGHT DECISION.
AND THE DISCUSSION IS OVER.
CAN YOU ACCEPT THAT?
NOW GO DO YOUR JOB!
YES, SIR.
I GOT WHAT I NEEDED.
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO GET
A GOOD LOCK WHEN HE REAPPEARS.
WHEN WILL THAT BE?
JUST OVER 3 HOURS.
HOW'S YOUR SHIP?
WE'RE READY.
-YOU SAVED MY LIFE.
-FORGET IT.
YOU DIDN'T DESERVE
ANY OF THIS, JONATHAN.
I'M SORRY THIS
BECAME YOUR PROBLEM.
LET'S MAKE IT WORTHWHILE.
LET'S GET QUINN BACK.
[ SIGHS ]
I'M SCARED.
I DON'T BLAME YOU.
I'VE WAITED
SO LONG FOR THIS MOMENT.
PLANNED FOR IT.
WHAT IF SOMETHING GOES WRONG?
WHAT IF I FAIL?
ON THE DAY BEFORE I ENTERED
FLIGHT TRAINING,
I ASKED MY FATHER
PRETTY MUCH THE SAME THING.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
"DON'T FAIL."
HENRY NEVER WAS A POET.
HE DIDN'T NEED TO BE.
[ BEEPING ]
ANY MOMENT NOW.
T'POL?
NOTHING.
[ BEEPING ]
-Captain.
-GO AHEAD.
B-DECK, SECTION 8.
CONFINEMENT BEAM.
WIDEST POSSIBLE SPREAD.
WAY AHEAD OF YOU.
GOT A LOCK ON SOMETHING.
PATTERN'S GOOD.
LET ME.
ENERGIZING.
WE NEED MORE POWER.
THAT'S ALL WE'VE GOT.
IT'S WORKING.
QUINN!
NO. NO!
COMPLETE
THE TRANSPORT SEQUENCE.
I DON'T HAVE
A STRONG ENOUGH SIGNAL.
RECALIBRATE
THE CONFINEMENT BEAM.
THAT WON'T HELP GET US A LOCK.
JUST DO IT.
I'M READING MASSIVE
CELLULAR DETERIORATION.
-THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
-HE'S LOSING COHESION.
IF HE MATERIALIZES,
HE'LL DIE IN SECONDS.
I CAN REVERSE THE DAMAGE
BY CROSS-PHASING THE STREAM
THE TRANSPORTER CAN'T DO THAT.
I BUILT THE DAMN THING!
I'M LOSING HIS VITAL SIGNS.
-EMORY.
-GET AWAY FROM ME.
TIE IN THE SECONDARY BUFFERS.
-THERE'S NOT ENOUGH TIME.
-DAD.
I CAN HOLD THE PATTERN.
JUST DO IT!
-DAD, LET HIM GO.
-NO!
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO FOR HIM.
I CAN'T LET HIM GO.
I CAN'T!
EMORY, YOU CAN'T SAVE HIM.
I'M SORRY, QUINN.
OH, QUINN.
DAD? WHAT'S WRONG?
QUINN, PLEASE FORGIVE ME.
PLEASE.
WHAT IS IT? WHAT?
[ SIGHS ]
[ SOBBING ]
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I COULDN'T LEAVE HIM
LIKE THAT.
IT'S BETTER TO BE
ALIVE OR DEAD,
NOT SOMEWHERE IN BETWEEN.
IF IT MEANS ANYTHING,
MY GUESS IS QUINN
WOULD FEEL THE SAME WAY.
I CAME HERE
TO BRING MY SON HOME.
I SUPPOSE
I ACCOMPLISHED MY GOAL.
I'VE BEEN IN CONTACT
WITH STARFLEET.
I IMAGINE THEY'RE NOT
TOO HAPPY WITH ALL THIS.
I'M SURE THEY'LL TAKE YOUR
ACHIEVEMENTS INTO CONSIDERATION.
I PERPETRATED A FRAUD
TO OBTAIN THE USE OF YOUR SHIP.
A MEMBER OF YOUR CREW
IS DEAD.
THERE'S NO WAY I'M GOING TO
AVOID THE CONSEQUENCES.
THERE'S ONE GOOD THING
TO COME OUT OF THIS.
DANI WON'T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT
TAKING CARE OF ME ANYMORE.
I MANAGED TO LET GO
OF ONE OF MY CHILDREN.
NOW I GUESS IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO LET GO OF THE OTHER.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
SHE SHOULD BE OUT HERE.
MAYBE THEY'LL PUT ME SOMEWHERE
WHERE I'LL BE USEFUL.
GET A CHANCE TO TEACH.
YOU'D PROBABLY BE GOOD AT IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I WOULDN'T BE BORING.
WHY SETTLE FOR
MAKING MYSELF MISERABLE
WHEN I CAN SPREAD
THE MISERY AROUND
TO AN ENTIRE CLASS
OF STUDENTS?
YOUR NEUROLYTIC ENZYMES
ARE AT THE SAME LEVEL
THEY WERE A WEEK AGO.
NO SIGN OF PA'NAR SYNDROME.
IT'S STILL
DIFFICULT FOR ME TO ACCEPT.
YOU WERE DIAGNOSED
WITH AN INCURABLE DISEASE.
NOW IT'S GONE.
IT'S A BIG ADJUSTMENT.
FROM WHAT I'VE BEEN READING,
SIMILAR DIAGNOSES HAVE TAKEN
PLACE ALL OVER VULCAN.
PEOPLE WITH PA'NAR
ARE COMING FORWARD.
IT'S NO LONGER A STIGMA.
THE KIR'SHARA IS
HAVING AN ENORMOUS IMPACT.
IT'S CLEARLY HAD
AN IMPACT ON YOU.
YOU, UM, SEEM MORE
CERTAIN OF YOURSELF.
I'VE NEVER FELT LESS CERTAIN.
UM...
YOU'RE RE-EXAMINING
YOUR CORE BELIEFS.
HMM.
SOMETHING MOST PEOPLE NEVER DO.
DO YOU HAVE A MOMENT?
SURE.
SOMETHING TELLS ME YOU'RE NOT
HERE TO TALK ABOUT MOVIE NIGHT.
I'M GOING THROUGH SOMETHING
THAT'S VERY COMPLICATED.
I KNOW.
I'M LEARNING,
IT SEEMS FOR THE FIRST TIME
WHAT IT TRULY
MEANS TO BE VULCAN.
WELL, MAYBE YOU CAN FILL ME IN.
NOT UNTIL I UNDERSTAND IT
MYSELF.
I DON'T THINK
THERE'LL BE TIME FOR...
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO SAY?
THAT YOU UNDERSTAND.
I DO.
IT'S NOT LIKE I DIDN'T
KNOW THIS WAS COMING.
AT LEAST MY WARP ENGINES
STILL NEED ME.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE RENDEZVOUSED
WITH THE SARAJEVO,
WHICH WILL BE RETURNING
EMORY AND DANICA TO EARTH.
SAFE JOURNEY.
AND YOU, JONATHAN.
COMMANDER.
AN HONOR WORKING WITH YOU.
SOME SUGGESTIONS.
MIGHT BOOST
YOUR TRANSPORTER RANGE
A FEW HUNDRED KILOMETERS.
COULDN'T RESIST.
I'LL CHECK IT OUT.
SAY GOODBYE TO PORTHOS.
GOOD LUCK.
MAYBE I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.