[ INDISTINCT
CONVERSATIONS ]
YOU'LL WIN IN EIGHT MOVES.
YOU'RE REALLY STARTING TO GET
A FEEL FOR THE GAME.
32 PIECES, 64 SQUARES.
IT'S NOT AS IF
IT'S DIFFICULT.
THE TOTAL NUMBER OF POSSIBLE
OUTCOMES IS LIMITED.
10 TO THE 123rd POWER.
THAT'S WHAT I MEAN.
CHESS IS SO PREDICTABLE.
I'M SURPRISED
ANYONE BOTHERS TO PLAY IT.
THEIR AVERAGE LIFESPAN'S
ONLY ABOUT 100 YEARS,
WITH NO TIME TO PLAY
ALL THE POSSIBLE GAMES.
-WHAT A WASTE.
-CAREFUL.
NO EMOTIONAL INVOLVEMENT.
I KNOW THE RULES.
OBSERVATION
WITHOUT INTERFERENCE.
HMM.
YOU'LL WIN IN FIVE MOVES.
I'M THE SHIP'S CHAMPION.
I WIN ALL THE TOURNAMENTS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HOW DO YOU THINK THEY'LL REACT
TO WHAT'S ON THIS PLANET?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT WE'RE HERE
TO FIND OUT.
BUT IN MY EXPERIENCE, ALL
PHYSICAL SPECIES ARE ALIKE.
I DON'T EXPECT
HUMANS WILL BE ANY DIFFERENT.
DO YOU THINK
OUR HOSTS WILL DIE TONIGHT?
IT'S POSSIBLE.
FOR SOME OF THE SPECIES
THAT HAVE COME HERE,
I'VE SEEN THE WHOLE CREW DIE.
FOR OTHERS, ONLY A FEW.
BUT SOMEBODY ALWAYS DIES.
ALWAYS.
YOUR MOVE.
[ SIGHS ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
I CAN'T WAIT TO GET BACK.
TWO DAYS AGO, YOU COULDN'T WAIT
TO GET OFF THE SHIP.
SIFTING THROUGH
A KLINGON GARBAGE DUMP --
NOT MY IDEA OF EXPLORING
STRANGE NEW WORLDS.
GETTING TIRED OF EXPLORATION,
ENSIGN?
ALL THE PLANETS
STARTING TO LOOK ALIKE?
NOT A CHANCE, SIR.
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
[ COUGHS ]
I FEEL LIKE
I'M STILL BREATHING DIRT.
SHUTTLEPOD 1 TO ENTERPRISE.
Welcome back. How did your
treasure hunt turn out?
WELL,
NOTHING WORTH BRINGING HOME.
THE KLINGONS
MUST HAVE BEEN HERE YEARS AGO.
ALL THEY LEFT WAS
AN OLD POWER CELL
AND A BUNCH
OF EMPTY RATION PACKS.
AND A LATRINE.
YEAH.
A LONG, HOT SHOWER'S
LOOKING PRETTY GOOD.
SHUTTLEPOD 1 OUT.
[ COUGHING ]
COMMANDER?
WHAT'S -- WHAT'S WRONG?
TAKE OVER.
GO TO DOCK.
[ COUGHING ]
SHUTTLEPOD 1 TO ENTERPRISE.
I have a medical emergency.
Commander Tucker's collapsed.
CAN YOU BRING THE SHUTTLEPOD IN?
YES, SIR.
AT LEAST IN SIMULATIONS.
SLOW AND STEADY, ENSIGN.
I'LL SEE YOU IN DECON.
UNDERSTOOD.
CALL PHLOX.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TRIP, HOW YOU FEELING?
OHH, LIKE I'VE BEEN GUT-PUNCHED
BY A TELLARITE.
DOCTOR, SHOULD WE
START WITH THE BIO-GEL?
NOT UNTIL WE KNOW
WHAT WE'RE DEALING WITH.
THREE OTHER LANDING PARTIES
RETURNED FROM THE SURFACE
WITH NO ILL EFFECTS.
WE NEED TO CHECK OUT
THE SHUTTLEPOD, TOO,
SEE IF ANY OF ITS ENVIRONMENTAL
SYSTEMS WERE AT FAULT.
I CAN DO THAT, CAPTAIN.
I SHOULD HAVE
THOUGHT OF THAT MYSELF.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE, TRIP.
PHLOX NEEDS BLOOD SAMPLES.
HERE'S THE MED KITS.
[ COUGHS ]
HOSHI, WHAT IS IT?
BEFORE COMMANDER TUCKER PASSED
OUT, HE STARTED COUGHING.
ARE YOU FEELING
ANY OTHER SYMPTOMS?
[ COUGHING ]
I'M GONNA GUESS THAT'S A YES.
I'LL PREPARE
ANTI-NAUSEA MEDICATION.
GET ME THOSE BLOOD SAMPLES, HMM,
AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ANYTHING?
WHATEVER'S AFFLICTING THEM,
IT'S NOT SHOWING UP
ON THE STANDARD SCANS.
-DOESN'T SOUND GOOD.
-IT'S NOT.
I STUDIED YOUR REPORT ON HOW
THE KLINGONS REACTED
TO THE INFECTION.
THEIR RESPONSE WAS TYPICAL
FOR A SPECIES
AT THEIR LEVEL
OF DEVELOPMENT.
THE KLINGON COMMANDER
DIDN'T LET HIS LANDING PARTY
BACK ON HIS SHIP.
-YOUR POINT?
-CAPTAIN ARCHER DID.
CAPTAIN ARCHER'S DONE NOTHING
DIFFERENT FROM THE KLINGONS.
THE LAUNCH BAY AND DECON CHAMBER
ARE COMPLETELY ISOLATED
FROM THE REST OF THE SHIP.
SO IT DOESN'T MATTER
IF AN INFECTED LANDING PARTY
COMES ABOARD.
PRECISELY.
HUMANS DON'T WANT TO INTERACT
WITH DYING CREWMATES
ANY MORE THAN KLINGONS DID.
IF IT WAS LEFT TO ME, I'D STOP
OUR OBSERVATIONS IMMEDIATELY.
WE HAVE NOTHING MORE TO LEARN
FROM HUMANS.
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
THEY'RE SHOWING CONCERN
FOR EACH OTHER.
THE CARDASSIANS DID THAT WHEN
THEY WERE HERE, DIDN'T THEY?
BUT IN THE END, THEY KILLED
THEIR INFECTED CREW,
JUST AS THE KLINGONS DID.
THE ONLY DIFFERENCE IS THE TIME
IT TOOK TO REACH THAT DECISION.
MAYBE THE HUMANS
WILL SURPRISE US.
I'VE BEEN OBSERVING ALIENS
FOR 800 YEARS.
I'VE YET TO BE SURPRISED.
STILL,
WE SHOULD FOLLOW PROTOCOL.
START QUESTIONING
THE INFECTED CREW.
I'LL CHECK IN
WITH THE DOCTOR.
OKAY.
THIS IS FOR NAUSEA,
MUSCLE PAIN,
AND A COUGH SUPPRESSANT.
I'M NOT COUGHING ANYMORE.
NEITHER ARE YOU.
MAYBE WE'RE GETTING BETTER.
WELL, DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
COMMANDER.
HOSHI. JUST WANTED TO SAY HI.
UH, WE'RE A LITTLE BUSY
RIGHT NOW, TRAVIS.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT'S IN THE HYPOSPRAY?
SOMETHING FOR OUR SYMPTOMS.
YEAH. PHLOX DOESN'T KNOW
WHAT'S WRONG WITH US YET.
HAVE EITHER OF YOU
FACED SERIOUS ILLNESS BEFORE?
AREN'T YOU
SUPPOSED TO BE ON DUTY?
I WAS CURIOUS TO KNOW
HOW YOU COMPARE THIS EXPERIENCE
WITH OTHER ILLNESSES
YOU MIGHT HAVE CONTRACTED.
TRAVIS...WE REALLY NEED
TO GET SOME SLEEP.
I ONLY HAVE
A FEW MORE QUESTIONS.
-THANKS FOR STOPPING BY.
-BUT --
AH, LIEUTENANT REED.
SOMETHING I CAN DO FOR YOU?
HEADACHE.
OF COURSE. YEAH, JUST A MOMENT.
ARE THESE THE BLOOD TESTS
FOR COMMANDER TUCKER
AND ENSIGN SATO?
THAT'S CORRECT.
HUH. I'M NOT DETECTING
ANY VASCULAR INVOLVEMENT.
HMM?
YOUR HEADACHE.
NOT A BAD ONE, I TAKE IT?
OH, NO, NOT YET.
ALTHOUGH IT FEELS
LIKE IT COULD GET WORSE.
PREVENTATIVE MEASURE.
A LOT TO DO TODAY.
MILD ANALGESIC IT IS.
AH.
DOCTOR, I'M CURIOUS TO KNOW
HOW YOU THINK
THESE TESTS WILL HELP YOU
DEVELOP AN EFFECTIVE TREATMENT.
SO AM I.
I MEAN, ARE YOU
APPROACHING THIS STRICTLY
ON A SYMPTOMATIC LEVEL,
OR DO YOU BELIEVE
THERE'S ANY SIMILARITY
TO OTHER CONDITIONS
YOU'VE SEEN IN THE PAST?
[ CHUCKLES ]
LIEUTENANT, I BELIEVE I CAN
PUT YOUR MIND AT EASE.
IF YOUR COLLEAGUES HAVE RETURNED
WITH A CONTAGIOUS ILLNESS,
THERE IS NO WAY IT CAN SPREAD
TO THE REST OF THE SHIP.
WE ARE ALL QUITE SAFE.
I'M NOT WORRIED
ABOUT THAT, NO.
I'M INTERESTED
IN THE METHODOLOGY --
OUT! OUT! OUT!
I HAVE A LOT TO DO AS WELL.
HMM?
YOU EVER SEE
"THE ANDROMEDA STRAIN"?
STRAIN OF WHAT?
IT'S A MOVIE,
MID-20th CENTURY.
LET ME GUESS.
DR. ANDROMEDA
BUILDS A MONSTER,
AND IT KILLS HIM
IN THE END.
IT'S ABOUT
AN EXTRATERRESTRIAL DISEASE.
ALL YOUR MOVIES ARE THE SAME.
I CAN'T KEEP
THE STORIES STRAIGHT.
THIS REMINDS ME OF MY DORM ROOM
AT STARFLEET TRAINING.
GOT INTO A LOT OF TROUBLE
AT OLD STC.
I GOT KICKED OUT.
WELL, YOU CAN'T STOP THERE.
IN MY SECOND MONTH, I...
I HAD A DIFFERENCE OF OPINION
WITH THE COMPANY COMMANDER.
I BROKE HIS ARM.
CAN I ASK WHY?
POKER.
YOU BROKE HIS ARM PLAYING CARDS?
HE TRIED TO SHUT DOWN A GAME
I WAS RUNNING
FOR SOME OF THE RECRUITS AND
A COUPLE OF THE TRAINING STAFF.
HOLD ON.
YOU RAN A FLOATING
POKER GAME AT STC?
THE WAY THE REGULATIONS
ARE WORDED,
GAMBLING WAS
AN HONOR VIOLATION
ONLY IF IT TOOK PLACE
DURING DUTY HOURS.
SO I RAN THE GAME
ON WEEKENDS.
ONE NIGHT
MY C.C. SHOWED UP,
TRIED TO SWEEP ALL THE CHIPS
OFF THE TABLE, AND I --
WELL, I HAVE A BLACK BELT
IN AIKIDO.
I THINK HE WAS JUST UPSET THAT
I HADN'T INVITED HIM TO PLAY.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I GOT A BAD-CONDUCT DISCHARGE.
HOW THE HELL DID YOU END UP
ON ENTERPRISE?
STARFLEET NEEDED
LANGUAGE SPECIALISTS
MORE THAN THEY NEEDED TO MAKE
AN EXAMPLE OUT OF ME.
THEY LET ME BACK IN
ON PROBATION,
AND [SIGHS] HERE I AM.
HUH.
THE CLOSEST CLASSIFICATION
IT MATCHES IS A VIRUS.
HIGHLY CONTAGIOUS.
SILICON-BASED.
THIS IS AN M-CLASS PLANET.
ALL LIFE-FORMS DOWN THERE
SHOULD BE CARBON-BASED.
I CAN ONLY SURMISE
THE VIRUS WAS BROUGHT HERE,
PERHAPS BY A METEORITE,
WHICH COULD EXPLAIN WHY
ONLY ONE OF OUR LANDING PARTIES
ENCOUNTERED IT.
IS THERE A TREATMENT?
THERE'S NO RECORD
OF ANYTHING LIKE IT
IN THE DENOBULAN DATABASE.
THEN IT'S UP TO YOU.
I'LL DO ALL I CAN, CAPTAIN,
BUT AT THE RATE THE PATHOGEN
IS REPRODUCING,
COMMANDER TUCKER
AND ENSIGN SATO
HAVE LESS THAN FIVE HOURS
TO LIVE.
THE DOCTOR
IDENTIFIED THE PATHOGEN.
AH.
THAT HAPPENS 37% OF THE TIME.
BUT NO ONE'S MADE THE DECISION
TO ABANDON
THE INFECTED CREWMEMBERS.
THEN THIS WILL LIKELY BE ONE
OF THE TIMES WHEN EVERYONE DIES.
HMM.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-TRAVIS.
[ SIGHS ]
IF THAT'S YOU AGAIN...
IT'S ME.
NEXT TIME I ASK
TO GO ON A LANDING PARTY,
TALK ME OUT OF IT, OKAY?
YOU'RE USUALLY TOO STUBBORN
TO BE TALKED OUT OF ANYTHING.
BUT I'LL DO MY BEST.
-HOW'S HOSHI?
-SLEEPING.
WHATEVER PHLOX GAVE US,
AT LEAST IT'S HELPING
WITH THE PAIN.
PHLOX IDENTIFIED WHAT'S CAUSING
ALL THE TROUBLE --
A SILICON-BASED VIRUS.
I DON'T SUPPOSE HE'S ON HIS WAY
OVER HERE WITH THE CURE.
HE'S WORKING ON IT.
SO IS T'POL.
SO THERE IS NO CURE.
NOT YET.
I'M GETTING THE IDEA
YOU'RE UP AGAINST A DEADLINE.
IF YOU MEAN
HOW MUCH TIME DO YOU HAVE,
IT'S TOO EARLY FOR
THAT KIND OF TALK.
YOUR OWN IMMUNE SYSTEM
COULD KNOCK THIS THING OUT.
I REMEMBER EXOBIOLOGY 101,
CAPTAIN.
HUMANS ARE CARBON-BASED.
OUR IMMUNE SYSTEM
CAN'T FIGHT SILICON.
DON'T YOU GIVE UP ON ME.
THERE'S STILL A BUNCH OF PLANETS
OUT THERE WE HAVEN'T SEEN.
GET SOME REST.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'RE LOOKING FOR SIGNS
OF ELEVATED INTELLIGENCE
IN THE SPECIES WE OBSERVE.
RATIONAL INTELLIGENCE, YES,
WHICH ARCHER HAS
NOT DEMONSTRATED.
THE LONGER THE INFECTED CREW
REMAIN ONBOARD,
THE GREATER THE RISK
THAT QUARANTINE WILL FAIL.
I'M SURE CAPTAIN ARCHER KNOWS
EXACTLY WHAT THE RISK IS.
MAYBE IT'S NOT AS IMPORTANT
TO HIM AS STANDING BY HIS CREW.
IT'S JUST AS PROBABLE
THAT HE HASN'T REALIZED
HOW HOPELESS THE SITUATION IS.
THERE'S A WAY TO BE SURE.
WE CHOSE THE HELMSMAN AND THE
ARMORY OFFICER FOR GOOD REASON.
THEY'RE BOTH STATIONED
ON THE BRIDGE,
YET NEITHER PLAYS A CRITICAL
ROLE IN A MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
WHICH IS WHY WE SHOULD
INHABIT THE DOCTOR AND
THE SCIENCE OFFICER.
ARCHER RELIES ON THEIR FINDINGS
TO MAKE HIS DECISIONS.
WE COULD WITNESS THAT
AS IT HAPPENS.
THE MORE PEOPLE WE INHABIT,
THE GREATER THE CHANCE THAT WE
WILL INADVERTENTLY INTERFERE.
THE MORE PEOPLE WE INHABIT, THE
MORE WE'LL BE ABLE TO OBSERVE.
HOW MANY LANGUAGES
CAN YOU SPEAK?
THAT'S NOT HOW IT WORKS.
THERE ARE
A LOT OF COMMON PATTERNS.
I'M JUST GOOD
AT HEARING THEM, THAT'S ALL.
GOOD?
YOU'RE A GENIUS,
THE WAY YOU CAN PICK UP
AN ALIEN LANGUAGE
YOU'VE NEVER HEARD BEFORE AND
START SPOUTING IT BACK TO THEM.
I GOT TO TELL YOU, I'VE ALWAYS
BEEN JEALOUS YOU CAN DO THAT.
I WISH I COULD FIX WARP ENGINES
WITH DUCT TAPE
AND A POCKETKNIFE.
IT -- IT'S...A BIT MORE
COMPLICATED THAN THAT.
SOMETIMES.
SERIOUSLY.
ENGINEERING,
BUILDING THINGS --
HAVE YOU ALWAYS
BEEN GOOD AT THAT?
MM...WHEN I WAS A KID,
NOT SO GOOD AT BUILDING.
BUT I WAS A TERROR WHEN IT CAME
TO TAKING THINGS APART.
MY FOLKS USED TO PUT
ALL OUR KITCHEN APPLIANCES
ON THE HIGHEST SHELVES.
ONE THANKSGIVING, I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT I WAS THINKING, BUT, UM,
I REMOVED EVERY SCREW
FROM THIS BIG DINING-ROOM TABLE
WE HAD.
IT WAS SO OLD, THE WOOD
SORT OF STUCK TOGETHER.
SO IT STAYED STANDING...
UNTIL MY DAD
PUT THE TURKEY DOWN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I SPENT THE NEXT MONTH
IN MY ROOM.
HOW OLD WERE YOU?
OH...24, 25.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HOW LONG HAVE THEY BEEN THERE?
WE DIDN'T SEE YOU THERE.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-WE DIDN'T WANT
TO INTERRUPT YOU.
HOW'S THE RESEARCH COMING?
WE'RE WAITING ON
NEW TEST RESULTS.
WE THOUGHT WE'D SEE
HOW YOU TWO WERE PROGRESSING.
YOU'RE THE ONES WITH
THE MEDICAL SCANNERS.
WE WERE MORE INTERESTED IN
DISCUSSING YOUR STATE OF MIND.
[ SIGHS ]
LOOK, IF YOU REALLY WANT
TO KNOW HOW WE FEEL,
WE'D BE A LOT BETTER KNOWING
YOU TWO WERE BACK IN SICKBAY
WORKING ON THE CURE FOR THIS.
OF COURSE.
WE'RE GOING THERE NOW.
COMMANDER, ENSIGN.
THEY BOTH CAME TO SEE US.
MAYBE THAT MEANS
THEY'RE ALMOST FINISHED.
YEAH, UNLESS THERE'S
NOTHING MORE THEY CAN DO.
THEY'RE VERY BRAVE,
THE WAY THEY'RE FACING DEATH.
THEIR COURAGE ISN'T AT QUESTION.
THEIR INTELLIGENCE IS.
YOU WANT THE HUMANS TO FAIL.
THIS ISN'T A COMPETITION.
EITHER A SPECIES'
INTELLIGENCE IS DEVELOPED
ENOUGH FOR FIRST CONTACT,
OR IT ISN'T.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD CONSIDER
OTHER QUALITIES IN MAKING
OUR DECISION.
THIS IS THE MEASURE
WE HAVE USED FOR 10,000 YEARS.
IT'S NOT OUR RESPONSIBILITY
TO CHANGE IT.
THEN WHOSE RESPONSIBILITY
IS IT?
THERE. IF PHLOX IS RIGHT
ABOUT THE VIRUS COMING
HERE ON A METEORITE,
THAT CRATER
MIGHT BE THE SOURCE OF IT,
WHICH MEANS
THE KLINGONS AT THIS CAMPSITE
MUST HAVE BEEN INFECTED, TOO.
SET UP A PRIORITY CHANNEL
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
WE NEED TO FIND OUT
WHICH KLINGON SHIP
EXPLORED THIS WORLD,
AND WHETHER OR NOT
THEY DEVELOPED A CURE.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THOSE ARE THE NEW TEST RESULTS
MY HOST IS WAITING FOR.
WE SHOULD LEAVE THESE CREATURES
TO THEIR WORK UNDISTURBED.
THE HELMSMAN AND THE ARMORY
OFFICER ARE BACK ON THE BRIDGE.
THE ALTERED IMMUNE RECEPTORS
WEREN'T EFFECTIVE.
THIS COULD INDICATE THE VIRUS IS
SENSITIVE TO IONIZING RADIATION.
AT LEVELS THAT WOULD BE FATAL
TO HUMANS, BUT IT'S A START.
I'LL PREPARE NEW SAMPLES
FOR TESTING.
[ PANTING ]
[ SPEAKING JAPANESE ]
HOSHI.
[ SPEAKING GERMAN ]
-[ SPEAKING FRENCH ]
-HOSHI, WAKE UP!
[ PANTING ]
I WAS BACK IN BRAZIL...
WHERE...THE SHUTTLE WAS COMING
TO TAKE ME TO ENTERPRISE.
THAT'S WHERE WE ARE.
CAPTAIN ARCHER NEEDED ME EARLY.
I DIDN'T GET THE CHANCE TO SAY
GOODBYE TO MY STUDENTS.
YOU'LL SEE THEM AGAIN.
I'VE HEARD FROM STARFLEET.
THEY'RE WORKING
THROUGH DIPLOMATIC CHANNELS
TO CONTACT THE KLINGONS,
BUT IT MIGHT NOT
BE NECESSARY.
THIS SPECTROGRAPH
IDENTIFIES A KLINGON ALLOY.
THAT'S THE SIGNATURE
OF STANDARD HULL PLATING.
I FOUND IT...HERE.
YOU'VE DETECTED
A DEBRIS CLOUD IN ORBIT.
IT'S WHAT'S LEFT OF
A KLINGON SHUTTLECRAFT --
THEIR RESPONSE
TO AN INFECTED LANDING PARTY.
THE COMMANDER
KILLED HIS OWN SHUTTLE CREW.
THEY DIDN'T EVEN PLEAD
FOR MERCY.
I MEAN,
THEY WOULDN'T, WOULD THEY,
BEING KLINGON?
CAPTAIN, DOES KNOWING WHAT THE
KLINGONS DID HELP US AT ALL?
AT LEAST WE KNOW
WE DON'T HAVE TO BOTHER
ASKING THEM IF
THEY HAVE A CURE.
BUT IF THEY HAD DEVELOPED ONE,
YOU'D ASK THEM FOR IT, RIGHT?
ON BENDED KNEE.
[ SPEAKING SPANISH ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
HOSHI.
WE'RE IN QUARANTINE
FOR A REASON.
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING,
BUT YOU CAN'T
BREAK THE LOCKOUT CODE.
MATH IS JUST ANOTHER LANGUAGE.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-[ ALARM SOUNDING ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
QUARANTINE BREACH ON "D" DECK.
THE DECON CHAMBER
HAS BEEN UNSEALED.
[ GASPING ]
SOMEONE'S OVERRIDING
THE SAFETY INTERLOCKS.
SHUT DOWN ALL POWER TO "D" DECK.
I WANT THOSE DOORS SEALED.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
HOSHI, YOU HAVE TO STOP.
THAT'S AN AIRLOCK.
YOU OPEN THOSE DOORS, WE DIE.
[ SPEAKING RUSSIAN ]
[ SIGHS ] HOSHI, COME ON.
I NEED TO TELL THEM...
[ BOTH GRUNT ]
[ GASPING ]
...WHILE THERE'S STILL TIME.
THE CAPTAIN WON'T LET US DOWN.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
TRIP TO, UH...
[ SIGHS ]
WHOEVER'S OUT THERE.
WE'RE BACK.
COMMANDER, I WANT YOU
TO SET YOUR HYPOSPRAY
FOR THREE UNITS OF SONAMBUTRIL.
THAT COULD DROP A HORSE.
WE CAN'T RISK HOSHI
WANDERING OFF AGAIN,
ESPECIALLY SINCE
IT SEEMS SHE CAN OVERRIDE
EVERY SECURITY SAFEGUARD
ON ENTERPRISE.
YEAH, SHE'S...FULL
OF SURPRISES TODAY.
SWEET DREAMS, HOUDINI.
[ SIGHS ]
ANYTHING ELSE?
IT'S YOUR TURN, TRIP.
COME ON, CAPTAIN.
COMMANDER, THE VIRUS
IS INCOMPATIBLE WITH
CARBON-BASED LIFE.
IT'S ATTACKING YOUR BODIES
IN WAYS I CAN'T PREDICT.
YOU THINK I'M GONNA
WANDER OFF, TOO,
START OPENING THE WRONG DOORS?
NOT IF YOU'RE SEDATED.
SORRY, TRIP.
[ SIGHS ]
COMMANDER.
I'M JUST WONDERING IF EITHER ONE
OF US WILL EVER WAKE UP AGAIN.
YOU SHOULD LIE DOWN
RIGHT AWAY.
I WON'T ARGUE WITH THAT.
HOW CLOSE ARE YOU
TO STOPPING THIS?
T'POL AND I HAVE ISOLATED A
SPECIFIC FREQUENCY OF RADIATION
THAT DISRUPTS THE SILICON MATRIX
OF THE VIRUS.
SOUNDS PROMISING.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE DOSAGE
REQUIRED WOULD BE LETHAL.
THERE'S GOT TO BE
SOME KIND OF A TRADEOFF --
A WAY TO PRODUCE
ENOUGH RADIATION
TO SLOW DOWN THE VIRUS
WITHOUT KILLING THE PATIENT.
THAT'S WHAT I'M WORKING ON.
WORK FASTER.
WE CAN STOP WHAT THIS VIRUS
IS DOING TO THEM.
THAT'S NOT WHY WE'RE HERE.
WE CAME TO OBSERVE
THEIR RESPONSE
TO THE UNEXPECTED,
NOT TO WATCH THEM SUFFER.
THIS IS NOT THE PLACE
TO BE HAVING THIS DISCUSSION.
I KNOW WHERE WE CAN TALK
UNDISTURBED.
[ SIGHS ]
THE SENSATIONS IN THIS HOST
ARE DIFFERENT FROM THE OTHERS.
I'M EXPERIENCING PHYSICAL PAIN.
SO AM I.
WHY SHOULD ANY SPECIES
HAVE TO ENDURE THIS WEAKNESS?
BECAUSE THE DESIRE TO OVERCOME
IT WILL SPUR THEM TO MOVE
BEYOND THE LIMITATIONS
OF THE PHYSICAL WORLD.
MAYBE THAT ISN'T TRUE
FOR ALL SPECIES.
IT WAS TRUE FOR US.
YOU CAN'T BE AWAKE.
NOT WITH THAT MUCH SONAMBUTRIL.
OUR ANCESTORS
WERE PHYSICAL BEINGS.
WELL, WHAT WORKED FOR US
MIGHT NOT WORK FOR EVERYONE.
HUMANS HAVE
DIFFERENT QUALITIES.
NOTHING I HAVEN'T
SEEN BEFORE.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
AGAINST THIS SPECIES?
WHAT DISTURBS ME
MOST ABOUT THE HUMANS
IS THEIR CAPACITY
FOR VIOLENCE.
EXTRAORDINARY.
KLINGONS EMBRACE VIOLENCE.
THE HUMANS TRY TO AVOID IT.
HUMANS SAY THEY AVOID IT,
BUT THEIR WORDS DON'T...
WE'RE BEING OBSERVED.
AH, CAPTAIN, T'POL,
I WAS JUST COMING TO SEE YOU.
THESE ARE BRAINWAVE READINGS
OF COMMANDER TUCKER
AND ENSIGN SATO.
WHAT IS THE SIGNIFICANCE?
THE PATTERNS AREN'T HUMAN.
DID YOU KNOW THEY HAD
THIS CAPABILITY?
HE MUST HAVE USED
DENOBULAN TECHNOLOGY.
I SEE.
ARE YOU RESPONSIBLE FOR WHAT
HAPPENED TO MY PATIENTS?
WE HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
WE COME HERE ONLY TO STUDY
HOW PHYSICAL SPECIES
REACT TO THE UNKNOWN.
YOU CAN HELP BY TELLING US
HOW YOU DETECTED OUR PRESENCE.
THAT HAPPENS IN LESS THAN 2%
OF OUR MISSIONS.
COMMANDER TUCKER AND ENSIGN SATO
WERE SEDATED.
THEY SHOULDN'T HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO STAND AND TALK.
IT'S BEEN SO LONG
SINCE WE HAD PHYSICAL FORM,
WE WEREN'T ABLE TO DISTINGUISH
SLEEP FROM SEDATION.
WE'LL REMEMBER NEXT TIME.
IS THERE ANYTHING YOU CAN DO
TO HELP MY PATIENTS?
WE'RE HERE TO OBSERVE.
WE CAN'T INTERFERE.
YOU'RE INTERFERING WITH ME!
OUR SUBJECTS ARE HUMAN.
YOU'RE DENOBULAN.
YOU WERE INHABITED A FEW HOURS
AGO -- AN INTRIGUING EXPERIENCE.
I HAVE NO RECOLLECTION OF THAT.
MEMORIES ARE SIMPLE TO ADJUST.
YOU'RE GOING TO ADJUST MINE
AGAIN, HMM,
SO I WON'T REMEMBER A WORD
OF THIS ENCOUNTER?
OR WHAT YOU OBSERVED
IN THE DECON CHAMBER.
IF YOU HAVE THAT ABILITY,
YOU MUST BE ABLE TO HELP
MY PATIENTS.
WE COULD.
BUT WE WON'T.
THANK YOU
FOR YOUR HELP, DOCTOR.
NO WONDER YOU ERASE MEMORIES.
YOUR BEHAVIOR IS APPALLING!
ACCORDING TO WHAT I READ
ON THE DOCTOR'S MEDICAL PADD,
HE'S LEARNED HOW TO STOP
THE INFECTION.
I'VE SEEN SEVEN OTHER SPECIES
DEVELOP THE RADIATION CURE,
BUT NEVER IN TIME.
DID WE MAKE FIRST CONTACT
WITH ANY OF THEM?
OF COURSE NOT.
EXPENDING RESOURCES TO ATTEMPT
AN IMPOSSIBLE TASK
IS NOT A SIGN OF INTELLIGENCE.
THE CAPTAIN AND SCIENCE OFFICER
HAVE DECISIONS TO MAKE.
WE NEED TO RETURN
TO OUR ORIGINAL HOSTS.
FOR THE RADIATION
TO DESTROY THE VIRUS
WITHOUT KILLING THE PATIENT,
IT MUST BE PRECISELY FOCUSED.
THE EMITTERS IN THE DECON
CHAMBER AREN'T SUITABLE.
BUT THE BIO-SCANNER
IN SICKBAY IS.
TO MOVE THEM FROM DECON
TO SICKBAY,
WE'LL NEED TO EXPAND
THE QUARANTINED AREA.
THAT WON'T BE A PROBLEM.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THIS WORK.
[ ALARM BLARES ]
ENSIGN SATO'S CONDITION
IS DETERIORATING.
WE NEED TO HURRY.
ENGAGING QUARANTINE.
REED TO BRIDGE.
I CONFIRM A POSITIVE SEAL.
ENVIRONMENTAL SYSTEMS
ARE ISOLATED.
ENTERING THE QUARANTINE ZONE.
SHE'S GOING INTO OLIGEMIC SHOCK.
CAPTAIN, SHE'S DYING.
[ GASPING ]
GET HER ON THE BIO-SCAN BED.
SHE'S STOPPED BREATHING!
SOMEONE ALWAYS DIES.
[ SIGHS ] HOSHI.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-PHLOX!
-AH!
-WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THIS EQUIPMENT'S NOT
DESIGNED FOR E.V. GLOVES.
-I'LL BE YOUR HANDS.
-NO, CAPTAIN, NO!
RIGHT NOW,
ENTERPRISE NEEDS A DOCTOR
MORE THAN IT NEEDS A CAPTAIN.
ATTACH THE LEADS
20 CENTIMETERS APART.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IN 800 YEARS, NO ONE'S
EVER DONE THAT BEFORE?
NO.
NOT ONCE THEY KNOW
IT'S HOPELESS.
YOU NEED TO INJECT 40 UNITS
OF TRINEPHEDRINE INTO HER HEART.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
THAT CAN'T GO DEEP ENOUGH.
OLD-FASHIONED, BUT EFFECTIVE.
ANGLE IT SLIGHTLY MORE
TO THE RIGHT.
NOW, IN ONE QUICK MOTION,
INSERT IT THREE CENTIMETERS.
PRESS THE ACTIVATOR.
CLEAR!
[ DEFIBRILLATOR ZAPS ]
COME ON, HOSHI.
300 MILLIJOULES.
[ DEFIBRILLATOR ZAPS ]
CAPTAIN.
AGAIN!
340.
[ DEFIBRILLATOR ZAPS ]
[ FLATLINE ]
SHE'S GONE.
CAPTAIN, HELP ME
WITH COMMANDER TUCKER.
HOW MANY HAVE TO DIE
BEFORE YOU WILL ADMIT HUMANS
ARE DIFFERENT?
WE NEED TO STOP THIS.
I WILL NOT DEPART
FROM PROTOCOL.
THE INCIDENT ISN'T OVER.
WHEN THE FIRST DEATH
OCCURS ON THE SHIP,
THERE'S A 68% CHANCE THE REST OF
THE CREW WILL BECOME INFECTED.
AND WHAT MORE WILL THAT TEACH US
ABOUT THEM?
ALL THIS WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
WHETHER WE WERE HERE OR NOT.
WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD BE.
WE NEED TO MOVE HIM
INTO THE SCANNER.
[ PANTING ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ GASPS ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
IT DIDN'T WORK.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
NOT YOUR FAULT, DOCTOR.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE I CAN DO
FOR COMMANDER TUCKER,
BUT YOU'VE STILL GOT
A FEW HOURS.
THERE HAS TO BE SOMETHING ELSE
I -- I CAN TRY.
YOU SHOULD CONTINUE YOUR WORK
ON THE BRIDGE --
LESS CHANCE OF SOMETHING
GOING WRONG WITH YOUR SUIT.
I WON'T GIVE UP.
YOU KNOW WHERE TO FIND ME.
ARCHER TO T'POL.
T'POL HERE, CAPTAIN.
I TAKE IT
YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING.
I HAVE.
THEN YOU KNOW
YOU'RE IN COMMAND.
YES, CAPTAIN.
I WOULD LIKE TO THINK
YOU'LL STAY IN COMMAND.
DON'T LET ADMIRAL GARDNER SNEAK
IN SOMEONE OVER YOUR HEAD.
I'LL DO MY BEST.
I KNOW YOU WILL.
I NEED TO LOOK AFTER
TRIP NOW.
WE'LL TALK AGAIN WHEN...
WE'LL TALK AGAIN.
CAPTAIN.
IF COMMANDER TUCKER
BECOMES CONSCIOUS...
I'LL LET YOU KNOW RIGHT AWAY.
ARCHER OUT.
[ WHEEZING ]
I HAVE SUCH RESPECT FOR YOU,
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
TRIP?
NOT EXACTLY.
I'M AN ORGANIAN,
A NON-PHYSICAL LIFE-FORM.
TRIP IS MY HOST.
WHAT DID YOU DO TO HIM?
NOTHING.
WE NEVER INTERFERE
IN THE NATURAL DEVELOPMENT
OF OTHER SPECIES.
WE ONLY OBSERVE.
DID YOU KNOW
ABOUT THE SILICON VIRUS?
THAT'S WHY WE COME HERE --
TO SEE HOW DIFFERENT SPECIES
REACT WHEN THEY ENCOUNTER IT.
YOU KNEW ABOUT THE VIRUS THAT
KILLED TWO MEMBERS OF MY CREW,
AND YOU DIDN'T WARN US?
I WANTED TO,
BUT IT'S NOT UP TO ME.
YOU'RE BREAKING
EVERY RULE WE HAVE.
BECAUSE THEY DON'T APPLY
TO THIS SPECIES.
THAT IS NOT OUR DECISION
TO MAKE.
IF WE DON'T CHALLENGE
THE RULES --
I DON'T CARE ABOUT YOUR RULES.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENS
TO TRIP AND HOSHI
WHEN YOU'RE FINISHED
WITH THEIR BODIES.
WE HAVE TO LEAVE THEM
AS THEY ARE.
DEAD?
I UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU WON'T GET INVOLVED
WITH A SPECIES'
NATURAL DEVELOPMENT.
I'VE FACED THAT DECISION MYSELF.
IT ISN'T AN EASY ONE TO MAKE.
THEN WE AGREE.
NO, WE DON'T.
OUR ENCOUNTER WITH THE VIRUS
WAS AN ACCIDENT,
ONE THAT YOU
COULD HAVE PREVENTED.
THEN HOW WOULD WE
EVER LEARN ABOUT YOU?
ASK US. TALK TO US.
JUST LIKE YOU'RE DOING NOW.
TALKING IS A LIMITED FORM
OF COMMUNICATION FOR US.
WE'RE MUCH MORE ADVANCED
THAN HUMANS.
NOT FROM WHERE I'M STANDING.
MAYBE YOU'VE EVOLVED INTO BEINGS
WITH ABILITIES
I CAN'T COMPREHEND,
BUT YOU'VE PAID
A HELL OF A PRICE.
YOU'VE LOST COMPASSION
AND EMPATHY --
THINGS THAT GIVE LIFE MEANING.
AND IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES
TO BE ADVANCED...
I DON'T WANT ANY PART OF IT.
WE'RE LEAVING NOW, CAPTAIN.
YOU WON'T REMEMBER A THING
ABOUT OUR PRESENCE.
[ COUGHING ]
AND IN THREE HOURS,
YOU'LL DIE AS WELL.
NO.
WE HAVE THE POWER
TO SAVE THEM ALL.
ARE YOU DEFYING ME?
I'M DEFYING THE ENTIRE PROTOCOL.
WHAT ARCHER HAS DONE TODAY,
HIS ACT OF COMPASSION --
YOU'VE NEVER
WITNESSED THAT BEFORE.
IN TIME,
WE'LL STUDY OTHER HUMANS.
THERE'S ANOTHER WAY.
EXPERIENCE COMPASSION
FOR YOURSELF.
YOU WANT TO KNOW WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE HUMAN,
YOU NEED TO DO MORE
THAN OBSERVE.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-Archer to the bridge.
T'POL. GO AHEAD.
You wanted to know
when Trip was awake.
YES.
Well, you better
get down here,
because he's talking up a storm,
and so is Hoshi.
-CAPTAIN, HOSHI --
-You too, Phlox.
Maybe one of you can tell me
what the hell just happened.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU'RE ALL
COMPLETELY FREE OF THE VIRUS.
IT HAS TO HAVE BEEN
A DELAYED REACTION
TO COMMANDER TUCKER'S
RADIATION TREATMENT.
BUT HOW IT SPILLED OVER
TO YOU AND HOSHI,
I HAVE NO EXPLANATION.
OBVIOUSLY,
THE PATHOGEN'S BEHAVIOR
IS MORE UNPREDICTABLE
THAN WE ASSUMED.
I'M SURE SOMEONE AT STARFLEET
MEDICAL WILL FIGURE IT OUT.
BUT FOR NOW, WE'RE GONNA LEAVE
A WARNING BEACON IN ORBIT HERE
AND MAKE SURE
WHAT HAPPENED TO US
NEVER HAPPENS
TO ANYONE AGAIN.
YOU REALIZE THE CONSEQUENCES
OF WHAT WE'VE DONE.
WE WILL NEVER BE ABLE TO OBSERVE
ANOTHER SPECIES
ENCOUNTER THIS VIRUS.
GOOD.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD
TO MAKING MY FIRST REPORT.
AFTER 10,000 YEARS,
THE RULES NEED TO CHANGE.
THESE HUMANS HAVE NOT BEEN
A GOOD INFLUENCE ON YOU.
I WOULD NOT ENCOURAGE
FURTHER ENCOUNTERS.
I DON'T THINK
WE CAN AVOID THEM.
I'M GOING TO RECOMMEND
THAT WE START PREPARATION
FOR AN OFFICIAL
FIRST-CONTACT MISSION.
INDEED.
AND AT THE RATE
THEY'RE PROGRESSING,
THAT'LL BARELY GIVE US
5,000 YEARS TO PREPARE.
THEN WE'D BETTER GET STARTED.