[ GASPS ]
BRIDGE TO ENGINEERING.
ENGINEERING, RESPOND!
[ FIRE CRACKLING ]
[ BEEPS ]
THIS IS THE WARSHIP KUMARI
CALLING IMPERIAL COMMAND.
WE'VE BEEN ATTACKED
BY A TELLARITE VESSEL.
PRIMARY SYSTEMS HAVE FAILED.
-REQUEST IMMEDIATE --
-[ EXPLOSION ]
ALERT.
WARP CONTAINMENT BREACH
IN TWO MINUTES.
TELLARITE SWINE!
THEY'LL PAY FOR THIS.
[ BEEPS ]
THIS IS SHRAN.
ALL CREW TO THE ESCAPE PODS!
ABANDON SHIP.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
THE FOOD ON THIS SHIP
ISN'T FIT FOR ANIMALS.
THAT MANGY PET OF YOURS
WOULD PROBABLY TASTE BETTER.
YOU CAN EITHER TAKE ME HOME
OR FIND A NEW CHEF.
IT'S THAT SIMPLE.
OH, SOMETHING ELSE.
I WANT NEW QUARTERS.
IS THAT SO?
FOR ONE THING,
MY ROOM IS TOO SMALL.
THERE ARE PLASMA CONDUITS
RUNNING ACROSS THE CEILING.
IT'S NOISY,
IT KEEPS ME UP ALL NIGHT.
MAYBE YOU'D SLEEP BETTER
IN THE CARGO BAY.
WHAT DID YOU SAY TO ME?
THIS IS A STARSHIP,
NOT A LUXURY LINER.
IF YOU'RE NOT SATISFIED
WITH THE ACCOMMODATIONS,
WE CAN LEAVE YOU BEHIND
IN A SHUTTLEPOD.
MAYBE YOU'LL HAVE BETTER LUCK
WITH WHOEVER PICKS YOU UP.
AND IF YOU DON'T LIKE
CHEF'S FOOD, DON'T EAT IT.
FROM THE LOOKS OF THINGS,
YOU SHOULD PROBABLY SKIP
THE DESSERT TABLE
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT.
THAT WAS A NICE TOUCH.
[ LAUGHS ]
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M SUPPOSED TO SPEAK
TO THEIR AMBASSADOR LIKE THAT.
UH, TELLARITES ALWAYS HAVE
A LITANY OF COMPLAINTS.
IT'S HOW THEY START ARGUMENTS
WITH PEOPLE THEY'VE JUST MET.
EVEN IF THEY HAVE NOTHING
TO COMPLAIN ABOUT?
IN THAT CASE,
THEY'LL JUST INSULT YOU.
WHATEVER THEY SAY,
YOU HAVE TO RESPOND IN KIND,
OTHERWISE THEY'LL TAKE OFFENSE.
A SPECIES THAT
ACTUALLY THRIVES ON ARGUING.
THEY PROBABLY MAKE
GOOD POLITICIANS.
THANKS FOR THE DRY RUN.
UH, SIR?
I WASN'T KIDDING ABOUT PORTHOS.
YOU THINK HE'S MANGY?
NO. BUT YOU MIGHT WANT TO
KEEP HIM OUT OF SIGHT.
TELLARITES CONSIDER CANINES
SOMETHING OF A, UH, DELICACY.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
NOVEMBER 12, 2154.
WE'VE ARRIVED IN ORBIT
OF TELLAR PRIME.
STARFLEET'S ORDERED US
TO TRANSPORT THEIR AMBASSADOR
TO A NEUTRAL PLANET
DESIGNATED AS BABEL
WHERE EARTH'S MEDIATORS
WILL TRY TO SETTLE
A LONG-STANDING TRADE DISPUTE
BETWEEN THE TELLARITES
AND THE ANDORIANS.
EVERYTHING READY
FOR OUR GUESTS?
WELL, JUST ABOUT.
BUT MY PEOPLE ARE
WORKING TRIPLE SHIFTS
TRYING TO FINISH
THAT MUD BATH THEY WANTED.
MUD BATH?
APPARENTLY, THE AMBASSADOR LIKES
A GOOD SOAK IN THE MORNING.
SOMETHING I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THESE TELLARITES
HAVE WARP SHIPS.
SO WHY DO WE HAVE TO TAKE THEM
TO THE CONFERENCE?
BABEL'S ON THE FAR SIDE
OF ANDORIAN SPACE.
THEY WON'T ALLOW TELLARITE SHIPS
TO PASS THROUGH THEIR TERRITORY.
NOW WE'RE A SHUTTLE SERVICE.
WHEN ARE WE GONNA
GET BACK TO EXPLORING?
THIS TRADE DISPUTE IS
A LITTLE MORE URGENT.
IT COULD TURN INTO A SHOOTING
WAR IF THE CONFERENCE FAILS.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
YOU PEOPLE ARE EVEN UGLIER
THAN I REMEMBER.
[ GRUNTS ]
CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
WELCOME ABOARD.
AMBASSADOR GRAL.
I'M TOLD THIS SHIP IS
THE PRIDE OF STARFLEET.
I FIND IT SMALL
AND UNIMPRESSIVE.
FUNNY.
I WAS ABOUT TO SAY
THE SAME THING ABOUT YOU.
[ LAUGHING ]
YOU MAY SHOW US
TO OUR QUARTERS.
-[ BEEPS ]
-IT'S FAR TOO COLD
IN HERE.
WE'RE EXPECTED TO STAY
ON THIS SHIP FOR FIVE DAYS?
[ LAUGHS ]
SO HE SAYS, "WELL,
I'M NOT REALLY A PILOT."
[ CHUCKLES ]
UH, YOU DON'T GET IT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
WARM ENOUGH?
THE AMBASSADOR REQUESTED
THE TEMPERATURE BE INCREASED.
AGAIN?
YOU KNOW, I LIKE THESE PEOPLE
MORE THAN I THOUGHT I WOULD.
THEY DON'T HOLD ANYTHING BACK.
IT'S REFRESHING.
SPEAKING YOUR MIND FOR A CHANGE.
YOU DON'T FEEL FREE
TO SPEAK YOUR MIND
WITH THE REST OF US?
-OH, YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN.
-NO.
MAYBE YOU'D LIKE
TO EXPLAIN IT TO ME.
WHY DON'T YOU
CHANGE YOUR UNIFORM
BEFORE YOU
STINK UP THE PLACE?
AH, PRACTICING YOUR TELLARITE.
I GET IT.
WHEN IN ROME...
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
FORGET IT.
THE AMBASSADOR
WANTS TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
WHAT A SURPRISE.
HAVE WE CROSSED
INTO ANDORIAN SPACE?
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
THE LAST TIME I WAS HERE,
I WAS ON THE COMMAND DECK
OF ONE OF OUR CRUISERS,
DRIVING THOSE BLUE DEMONS
BACK INTO THEIR TERRITORY.
THE ANDORIANS CAME TO YOUR AID
DURING THE XINDI CRISIS.
THEY HELPED
SAVE MY PLANET.
SO WHY SHOULD WE TRUST HUMANS
TO MEDIATE THIS DISPUTE?
YOU OWE THEM YOUR LIVES.
EARTH WANTS A PEACEFUL OUTCOME
JUST AS MUCH AS YOU DO.
THAT ISN'T GOING TO HAPPEN
IF WE CHOOSE SIDES.
YOUR PEOPLE HAVE NO EXPERIENCE
IN INTERSTELLAR AFFAIRS.
IT DOESN'T SEEM THAT YOU HAVE
A LOT OF OTHER OPTIONS.
YOUR CHEF OBVIOUSLY
WENT TO A GREAT DEAL OF TROUBLE.
I'M TOLD THESE ARE
AUTHENTIC TELLARITE DISHES.
IF I'D WANTED TO EAT LIKE THIS,
I WOULD HAVE STAYED AT HOME.
I WAS EXPECTING TO SAMPLE
EARTH CUISINE ON THIS JOURNEY.
I'LL HAVE HIM
WHIP SOMETHING UP.
AHA.
Captain Archer to the bridge.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ BEEPING ]
WE'VE PICKED UP A MESSAGE
ON AN ANDORIAN CHANNEL.
KUMARI CALLING
IMPERIAL COMMAND.
-BEEN ATTACKED.
-[ STATIC ]
...PRIMARY SYSTEMS
HAVE FAILED.
REQUEST IMMEDI--
[ STATIC ]
THAT'S IT.
THEY HAVE NO SHIPS
WITHIN RANGE.
HOW LONG TO INTERCEPT THEM
AT MAXIMUM WARP?
TWO HOURS.
ALTER COURSE.
CONTACT BABEL. LET THEM KNOW
WE'RE GOING TO BE DELAYED.
JUDGING BY
THE DEBRIS PATTERN,
I'D SAY
THEIR REACTOR BREACHED.
I'M DETECTING SIGNIFICANT
QUANTITIES OF DURANIUM ALLOY.
THIS WAS MOST LIKELY
AN ANDORIAN COMBAT VESSEL.
[ BEEPING ]
ESCAPE PODS.
MULTIPLE BIO-SIGNS.
BRING THEM INTO THE LAUNCH BAY.
TELL PHLOX TO STAND BY
FOR CASUALTIES.
THIS WOULD BE EASIER IF YOU'D
TAKE A FEW STEPS BACK.
I HOPE YOU'VE STUDIED
ANDORIAN PHYSIOLOGY.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
HOW MANY OF MY CREW
DID YOU RESCUE?
19.
OUR COMPLEMENT WAS 86.
YOUR DISTRESS CALL
SAID YOU WERE ATTACKED.
TELLARITES!
WE WERE
ESCORTING OUR AMBASSADOR
TO THE TRADE CONFERENCE
WHEN THEY DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
THE AMBASSADOR'S SHIP
WAS DESTROYED IN SECONDS.
TELLARITES CRIPPLED US
WITH THEIR NEXT SHOT.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ONE OF THEIR VESSELS
MANEUVER LIKE THIS ONE.
WHILE THOSE BARBARIANS
HAVE BEEN TALKING PEACE,
THEY'VE OBVIOUSLY BEEN IMPROVING
THEIR WARSHIPS.
WHY WOULD THE TELLARITES
AGREE TO LET EARTH
MEDIATE YOUR DISPUTE IF THEY
WERE PLANNING THIS STRIKE?
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD ASK THEM.
I SUGGEST YOU SCAN
FOR OUR DATA RECORDER.
IT WILL CONTAIN
THE SENSOR LOGS OF THE ATTACK.
WE SEEM TO KEEP RUNNING
INTO EACH OTHER, CAPTAIN.
IT'S FORTUNATE
ENTERPRISE WAS CLOSE BY.
IT'S NOT A COINCIDENCE.
WE'RE CARRYING
THE TELLARITE DELEGATION.
THEY'RE ABOARD THIS SHIP?
THESE AREN'T THE PEOPLE
WHO ATTACKED YOU.
THEY MAY KNOW WHO DID.
SHRAN!
YOU'RE ON MY SHIP.
YOU'D BETTER KEEP THEM
AWAY FROM US,
OR THERE WILL BE BLOODSHED.
[ BEEPING ]
I'VE ANALYZED
THESE HULL FRAGMENTS.
THE DAMAGE IS CONSISTENT
WITH TELLARITE PARTICLE CANNONS.
WHAT ABOUT THE BLACK BOX?
THE MEMORY CORE WAS DAMAGED.
BUT I WAS ABLE TO RECONSTRUCT
THE LAST FEW SECONDS
OF SENSOR DATA.
TELLARITES.
SET COURSE FOR ANDORIA.
BEST SPEED.
THESE ACCUSATIONS ARE ABSURD.
WE HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS ALLEGED ATTACK.
THE ANDORIAN SENSOR LOGS.
LOOK THEM OVER YOURSELF.
LOGS CAN BE FABRICATED.
YOU SAW THE DEBRIS FIELD.
FOR ALL WE KNOW, THEY DESTROYED
THE SHIP THEMSELVES.
ANDORIAN TECHNOLOGY
IS MORE ADVANCED THAN OURS.
ONE OF OUR CRUISERS
WOULDN'T STAND A CHANCE
AGAINST TWO OF THEIRS.
I WANT YOU TO SPEAK TO YOUR
PEOPLE, FIND OUT WHAT YOU CAN.
I AM NOT COMFORTABLE
WITH SO MANY ANDORIANS ABOARD!
CONTACT YOUR SUPERIORS.
HAVE THEM TRANSFERRED
TO ANOTHER VESSEL.
LET'S GET SOMETHING STRAIGHT.
YOU'RE JUST A PASSENGER
ON MY SHIP.
I GIVE THE ORDERS.
-WHERE ARE YOU TAKING THEM?
-BACK TO ANDORIA.
YOU CAN'T.
THEY'LL ARREST US.
THEY'LL HOLD US RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS INCIDENT.
IF YOU'RE INNOCENT,
I'M SURE YOU HAVE
NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT.
[ GROANS ]
TO THE KUMARI.
FROM WHAT I SAW...
SHE WAS A FINE SHIP
WITH A GOOD CREW.
I WAS IN COMMAND FOR 12 YEARS.
THE FIRST SHIP OF HER CLASS.
MOST OF THE CREW
I'D SERVED WITH EVEN LONGER.
THEY WERE MORE
THAN COLLEAGUES.
I KNEW THEIR SPOUSES,
THEIR CHILDREN.
I'M GRATEFUL TALAS SURVIVED.
IF I LOST HER...
I DIDN'T REALIZE
THERE WAS SOMETHING
GOING ON
BETWEEN THE TWO OF YOU.
IT'S A RECENT DEVELOPMENT.
IN THE PAST,
I NEVER WOULD HAVE CONSIDERED
A RELATIONSHIP WITH SOMEONE
UNDER MY COMMAND.
WHAT CHANGED?
ANDORIAN WOMEN ARE FAR MORE
AGGRESSIVE THAN EARTH FEMALES.
SHE MADE AN OVERTURE.
I HAD A CHOICE.
CHARGE HER WITH
ASSAULTING A SUPERIOR OR...
MATE WITH HER.
I HOPE YOU MADE
THE RIGHT DECISION.
I REGRET THAT YOU'RE DRAWN
INTO ANOTHER OF OUR CONFLICTS,
CAPTAIN.
I SEEM TO HAVE
A KNACK FOR IT.
I DOUBT THAT WAR
CAN BE AVOIDED THIS TIME
WHEN THAT SENSOR DATA
IS SEEN BY THE IMPERIAL COMMAND.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
WHY AGREE TO A CONFERENCE,
THEN ATTACK YOUR AMBASSADOR?
TELLARITES DON'T THINK
LIKE YOU OR I DO.
THEY'VE BEEN PROVOKING US
FOR MONTHS.
WE'VE LOST SIX FREIGHTERS
ALONG THE BORDER.
WE KNOW THEY'RE RESPONSIBLE.
TELLARITES CLAIM THEY'VE
LOST SHIPS OF THEIR OWN.
YOU'D ACCEPT THEIR WORD
OVER OURS?
[ BEEPS ]
T'Pol to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
There's a ship
on an intercept course.
It's Andorian.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
YOU EXPECTING COMPANY?
HAIL THEM.
[ BEEPS ]
-THEY'RE NOT RESPONDING.
-[ ALARM BEEPING ]
I'M READING A POWER BUILD-UP.
THEY'RE OPENING FIRE.
WHAT THE HELL ARE THEY DOING?
OUR WARP FIELD'S
DESTABILIZING.
WE'RE DROPPING TO IMPULSE.
CALL THEM OFF.
LET ME TALK TO THEM.
THIS IS COMMANDER SHRAN
OF THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
CALL OFF YOUR ATTACK!
MY CREW IS ABOARD THIS SHIP.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
ABORT YOUR ATTACK.
PHASE CANNONS, RETURN FIRE.
-[ BEEPING ]
-NO DAMAGE.
WE NEED TO GET THROUGH
THEIR SHIELDS. HOW?
THEY'RE GONNA KILL ALL OF US
IF YOU DON'T DO SOMETHING.
[ EXPLOSION ]
I NEED TO ACCESS
YOUR TARGETING ARRAY.
THESE ARE THE COORDINATES
TO THEIR SHIELD GENERATOR.
FIRE WHEN READY.
-DIRECT HIT.
-[ BEEPING ]
THEIR SHIELDS ARE
STILL AT MAXIMUM.
IMPOSSIBLE.
SHRAN!
OUR DORSAL PLATING'S
ALMOST GONE.
STARBOARD THRUSTERS ARE DOWN.
TORPEDOES, MAXIMUM YIELD.
THEY'RE MOVING OFF.
THERE'S A FLUCTUATION
IN THEIR POWER GRID.
GOOD WORK.
THAT WASN'T MY DOING, SIR.
I DIDN'T TARGET
THEIR POWER GRID.
YOUR GOVERNMENT
ASKED US TO BE A PART
OF THIS CONFERENCE,
AND NOW YOU'RE ATTACKING US?
THIS MAKES PERFECT SENSE,
CAPTAIN.
THEY SENT OUT A DISTRESS CALL
TO LURE YOU INTO A TRAP.
WE HAVE NO ARGUMENT
WITH STARFLEET.
YOUR PEOPLE
TRIED TO DESTROY THIS SHIP!
CAPTAIN, I ASSURE YOU,
WHAT HAPPENED
DOES NOT REPRESENT
THE WILL OR INTENT
OF MY GOVERNMENT.
ADMIT THE TRUTH.
THE IMPERIAL GUARD
NEVER WANTED
THIS CONFERENCE
TO TAKE PLACE.
THEY'VE OBVIOUSLY TAKEN MATTERS
INTO THEIR OWN HANDS.
ARE YOU IMPLYING THE
IMPERIAL GUARD'S BEEN DISLOYAL?
I DON'T HAVE TO
IMPLY ANYTHING.
THE FACTS SPEAK
FOR THEMSELVES.
THAT MAY NOT HAVE BEEN
AN ANDORIAN SHIP.
-WHAT?
-ITS SHIELD MATRIX
HAD A COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT CONFIGURATION.
WHAT IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO PROVE?
SEVERAL OF OUR WARSHIPS
HAVE BEEN REPORTED MISSING
OVER THE YEARS.
THE TELLARITES COULD HAVE
TAKEN ONE OF THEM,
ENHANCED ITS SYSTEMS.
[ LAUGHS ] HE'S SUFFERING
FROM PARANOIA, CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT PARANOID!
YOUR PEOPLE ARE
TRYING TO KILL US.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF YOUR LIES.
THAT'S ENOUGH!
[ GROWLS ]
YOU WANT TO FIGHT?
I'LL THROW BOTH OF YOU
IN THE BRIG.
YOU CAN TEAR EACH OTHER
TO PIECES.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
WHAT HAPPENED?
ARCHER CLAIMS
TO BE IMPARTIAL.
BUT IT'S OBVIOUS HE'S INCLINED
TO BELIEVE THE ANDORIANS.
WE MAY HAVE MADE A MISTAKE
IN TRUSTING THESE HUMANS.
THEY'VE POSTED SOLDIERS
OUTSIDE OUR QUARTERS.
WE'RE PRISONERS ON THIS SHIP.
HAVE YOU STOPPED TO CONSIDER
ARCHER MAY BE CONSPIRING
WITH THE ANDORIANS?
T'POL'S FOUND SOMETHING
YOU'RE GONNA WANT TO SEE.
WE RETRIEVED THIS FROM YOUR
SHIP'S DATA RECORDER.
THIS IS
THE POWER SIGNATURE
OF THE VESSEL
THAT DESTROYED THE KUMARI.
[ BEEPS ]
THIS SIGNATURE BELONGS
TO THE ANDORIAN SHIP
THAT ATTACKED ENTERPRISE.
THEY'RE IDENTICAL.
THAT CAN'T BE CORRECT.
EXAMINE THE DATA YOURSELF.
YOUR SENSORS
ARE UNSOPHISTICATED.
THERE'S BEEN A MISTAKE.
WE'VE CONFIRMED THE DATA.
WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING?
THAT THESE TWO VESSELS
ARE ACTUALLY THE SAME SHIP?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'M SUGGESTING.
BUT WE NEED TO
KEEP OUR MINDS OPEN.
THE TELLARITES HAVE VIOLATED
EVERY ACCORD
WE'VE MADE WITH THEM.
THEY CAN'T BE TRUSTED.
YOUR DESIRE FOR
A PEACEFUL RESOLUTION
IS BLINDING YOU
FROM THE TRUTH.
-COMMANDER, PERHAPS --
-I'VE HEARD ENOUGH FROM YOU!
VULCANS ARE EXPERT LIARS.
PERHAPS YOUR PEOPLE
ARE BEHIND THIS.
YOU'RE SPEAKING
TO MY FIRST OFFICER.
Tucker to the bridge.
GO AHEAD.
WARP ENGINES WILL BE
ONLINE IN 10 MINUTES.
WE'LL HAVE HULL PLATING BACK
WITHIN AN HOUR.
Keep me updated.
WE'VE LOCATED THE WARP TRAIL
OF THE SHIP THAT ATTACKED US.
WE'RE GOING TO FOLLOW IT.
SOME OF MY CREW ARE
IN SERIOUS CONDITION.
THEY NEED ATTENTION
FROM OUR PHYSICIANS.
IT'LL TAKE FOUR DAYS
TO GET TO ANDORIA.
BY THEN,
THAT SHIP WILL BE LONG GONE.
SOMETHING WRONG
WITH YOUR MEAL?
I'M JUST NOT HUNGRY.
DO YOU THINK
WE'RE MOVING TOO FAST?
COMMANDER TUCKER BELIEVES
IT'S SAFE TO MAINTAIN
THIS WARP FACTOR.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
EARTH'S GOT A LOT RIDING
ON THE OUTCOME OF THESE TALKS.
BUT I'M NOT SURE WE KNEW
WHAT WE WERE GETTING INTO.
THESE PEOPLE HAVE BEEN FEUDING
FOR OVER A CENTURY.
MAYBE WE SHOULD HAVE LET
YOUR GOVERNMENT HANDLE THIS.
ALTHOUGH OUR RELATIONS
HAVE IMPROVED RECENTLY,
IT'S CLEAR THE ANDORIANS
DON'T TRUST US.
ASIDE FROM BREATHING OXYGEN,
IT DOESN'T SEEM TO ME
THAT ANDORIANS AND TELLARITES
HAVE A HELL OF A LOT
IN COMMON.
THE SAME HAS BEEN SAID
ABOUT HUMANS AND VULCANS.
HOSHI TELLS ME
YOU GOT A TRANSMISSION
FROM VULCAN THIS MORNING.
IT WAS A PERSONAL MESSAGE.
IT WAS FROM KOSS.
OUR MARRIAGE HAS BEEN
OFFICIALLY DISSOLVED.
I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO APOLOGIZE FOR.
Bridge to Captain Archer.
ARCHER.
I believe we've found
the Andorian ship, sir.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
REPORT.
I'VE BEEN UNABLE
TO LOCATE THE MALFUNCTION.
THEN I SUGGEST YOU
DOUBLE YOUR EFFORTS.
THIS IS ENEMY TERRITORY.
WE CAN'T REMAIN HERE
ANY LONGER WITHOUT --
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
THERE'S A VESSEL APPROACHING.
SHOW ME.
YOU SAID YOU FOUND
THE ANDORIANS.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT, SIR.
THE WARP TRAIL
ENDS RIGHT HERE.
THEIR PRIMARY SYSTEMS
ARE OFFLINE.
HAIL THEM.
[ BEEPING ]
NO RESPONSE.
BIO-SIGNS ARE INDETERMINATE.
MAGNIFY.
ANY IDEA WHAT THE SPIKES ARE?
THEY APPEAR TO BE
SUBSPACE TRANSCEIVERS.
WHY WOULD THEY NEED SO MANY?
THEIR HULL IS ALSO LINED
WITH MULTI-SPECTRAL EMITTERS.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
I PREFER NOT TO SPECULATE.
FIND OUT
WHO THESE PEOPLE ARE.
TAKE A TEAM OF MACOs
WITH YOU.
THEIR LIFE SUPPORT'S OFFLINE.
BRING TRIP ALONG.
SEE IF HE CAN GET IT WORKING.
YOU TWO, START DOWN THERE.
YES, LIEUTENANT.
THIS WHOLE SECTION'S
DEPRESSURIZED.
[ GRUNTS ]
LET'S HOPE THE REST OF THIS SHIP
ISN'T AS CRAMPED.
I CAN'T READ ANYTHING
THROUGH THESE BULKHEADS.
STAY ALERT.
THE PROPULSION MATRIX
STILL ISN'T FUNCTIONING.
HOW MUCH LONGER?
THE REPAIRS ARE UNDERWAY.
-PREPARE TO OVERLOAD
THE CORE.
-WHAT?
IF WE CAN'T REPAIR
THE MATRIX IN TIME,
I'LL DO WHATEVER IS NECESSARY
TO KEEP IT AWAY
FROM STARFLEET.
[ BEEPS ]
TUCKER TO ENTERPRISE.
Go ahead.
WE HAVEN'T RUN INTO
ANY WELCOMING PARTIES YET.
WE'VE FOUND
A COMPUTER INTERFACE,
BUT THERE'S
NO POWER OVER HERE.
I'M GONNA NEED T'POL'S HELP
TO BRING IT ONLINE.
UPLINK YOUR SCANNER.
[ ENERGY HUMMING ]
-WHAT'S HAPPENING?
-I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
SIR.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
GET OUR PEOPLE BACK!
[ GRUNTING ]
AAH!
CAPTAIN, WE'RE READY
TO COME HOME WHENEVER YOU ARE.
THEY'VE REINFORCED
THEIR HULL PLATING.
WE CAN ONLY TRANSPORT
ONE AT A TIME.
TAKE CARENDER
AND MYERS FIRST!
ONE OF THE MACOs IS ABOARD.
THEY'VE HIT
OUR E.P.S. COUPLINGS.
SWITCH TO AUXILIARY.
TARGET THEIR WEAPONS ONLY.
UGH!
WE'RE LOSING HULL PLATING.
TRANSPORTER'S OFFLINE.
-DID WE GET EVERYONE?
-JUST THE MACOS.
T'POL.
THE PRIMARY
PHASE COIL IS FUSED.
IT'LL TAKE SEVERAL HOURS
TO REPAIR IT.
[ ALARM BEEPS ]
DECOMPRESSION ON C-DECK,
SECTION 3.
WE HAVE TO WITHDRAW.
ARCHER TO TRIP.
We've lost the transporter.
UNDERSTOOD.
Sit tight until we
come back for you.
WE'LL BE FINE, SIR.
GET US OUT OF HERE, TRAVIS.
MAXIMUM WARP.
THEY'RE RETREATING.
PURSUIT COURSE.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ AIR HISSING ]
TRIP!
[ GASPING ]
[ HISSING STOPS ]
YOU'RE DOWN TO EIGHT MINUTES.
[ SIGHS ]
THANKS.
WE'RE NOT GONNA GET VERY FAR
ONLY SHARING YOUR SUPPLY.
I'LL TRY TO GET THEIR
LIFE SUPPORT ONLINE.
RIGHT.
WITH OUR LUCK, THEY PROBABLY
BREATHE FLUORINE.
WARP 4.9.
THEY'RE STILL CLOSING.
WARP 5.
THEY'VE MATCHED OUR SPEED.
LET'S SEE WHAT THOSE
NEW INJECTORS CAN DO.
5.02.
.04.
5.06.
THEY'RE FALLING BEHIND.
THE INJECTOR'S STABILIZED.
WE'RE HOLDING SPEED.
MAINTAIN YOUR HEADING.
YOU'RE GOING TO WEAR OUT
THE DECK PLATING.
COMMANDER.
GRAL KNOWS MORE ABOUT THESE
ATTACKS THAN HE'S ADMITTING.
HOW CAN ARCHER BE SO BLIND?
WE HAVE NO CHOICE BUT TO LET HIM
DEAL WITH THE SITUATION.
I'M NOT GOING TO ENTRUST
THE SECURITY OF ANDORIA
TO THE PINK-SKINS
OR ANYONE ELSE!
WE TRUSTED
THE TELLARITES ONCE!
WE WON'T MAKE
THAT MISTAKE AGAIN.
WITH THE APPROPRIATE
PERSUASION,
GRAL WILL TALK.
I DOUBT ARCHER'S CAPABLE
OF A THOROUGH INTERROGATION.
THEN I'LL HAVE TO
QUESTION HIM MYSELF.
THERE ARE GUARDS
OUTSIDE OUR QUARTERS.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT DECK
THE AMBASSADOR'S ON.
CAN YOU BYPASS
THEIR SECURITY PROTOCOLS?
-ANY LUCK?
-I CAN'T FIND ANYTHING
THAT EVEN LOOKS LIKE
AN ATMOSPHERE RECYCLER.
I'M STARTING TO WONDER
IF THIS SHIP EVEN
HAS LIFE-SUPPORT.
THEY MUST HAVE ATMOSPHERE
ON THEIR BRIDGE.
WELL, LET'S HOPE
THEY DON'T MIND SHARING.
THE STARFLEET SHIP
HAS MOVED OUT OF SENSOR RANGE.
THE HUMANS HAVE SEEN TOO MUCH.
WE CAN'T ALLOW THEM TO ESCAPE.
THIS VESSEL IS A PROTOTYPE.
I TOLD YOU
IT WASN'T READY FOR COMBAT.
FIND THEM.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
OUR BATTLE DAMAGE
HAS BEEN REPAIRED,
AND WE'VE RESUMED OUR SEARCH
FOR THE ALIEN VESSEL.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I ANALYZED THE DATA
COMMANDER TUCKER SENT BACK.
THE SHIP DOESN'T APPEAR
TO BE TELLARITE OR ANDORIAN.
DO WE HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO BUILT IT?
THERE'S A REMOTE POSSIBILITY.
ITS POWER MATRIX
UTILIZES BORIDIUM CELLS.
WE ENCOUNTERED
A SIMILAR TECHNOLOGY
MORE THAN TWO YEARS AGO.
THE ROMULAN MINEFIELD.
BUT THE POWER CELLS
ON THOSE MINES
WERE MUCH LARGER
AND MORE PRIMITIVE.
I DID SAY IT WAS
A REMOTE POSSIBILITY.
IF THIS IS A ROMULAN SHIP,
WHY WOULD THEY BE STIRRING UP
TROUBLE SO FAR FROM HOME?
THEY HAVE BEEN KNOWN
TO ACT AGGRESSIVELY
AGAINST SPECIES
THEY SEE AS A THREAT.
WE'VE NEVER THREATENED THEM.
AS FAR AS I KNOW,
NEITHER HAVE
THE ANDORIANS OR TELLARITES.
MAYBE THEY'RE AFRAID
OF SOMETHING ELSE.
THE SPECIES IN THIS REGION HAVE
A HISTORY OF NOT GETTING ALONG.
THIS CONFERENCE
COULD HAVE BEEN
THE FIRST STEP
IN CHANGING THAT.
YOU BELIEVE
THEY FEAR AN ALLIANCE?
THE CONFERENCE HAS BEEN
POSTPONED INDEFINITELY.
IT DOESN'T SOUND LIKE
THERE'S GONNA BE AN ALLIANCE
ANY TIME SOON.
ANYTHING FROM TRIP?
WE'RE STILL TOO FAR AWAY
TO DETECT A COMM SIGNAL.
WELL, KEEP ME UPDATED.
[ THUDDING ]
ANOTHER ACCESS TUBE.
I'M STARTING TO WONDER
IF THIS SHIP EVEN HAS A BRIDGE.
YEAH.
YOUR AIR'S DOWN
TO 26 MINUTES, MALCOLM.
PERHAPS IT'S ON ONE
OF THE LOWER LEVELS.
THERE'S NO RULE
THAT SAYS THE BRIDGE
HAS TO BE
AT THE TOP OF THE SHIP.
YOU SEE THESE DATA CONDUITS?
UH-HUH.
CHANCES ARE THEY CONVERGE
ON THE BRIDGE.
SO, I UNDERSTAND OUR FIRST
OFFICER'S NO LONGER MARRIED.
YEAH?
WELL, I WAS WONDERING
WHAT YOUR INTENTIONS WERE.
WELL, WHO ARE YOU,
HER FATHER?
[ LAUGHS ] NO.
SIMPLY CURIOUS.
MALCOLM. MALCOLM!
WE'VE GOT SOMETHING.
WHAT IS IT?
A MANEUVERING THRUSTER.
PERHAPS THEY'LL BE KIND ENOUGH
TO GIVE US THE SPECS.
IT'S CHEMICALLY FUELED.
LIQUID HYDROGEN...
AND OXYGEN.
WE COULD REFILL OUR TANKS.
CAN I HELP YOU?
I WAS HOPING WE COULD TALK.
I DOUBT YOU'RE AWARE OF THIS.
HOW COULD YOU BE?
ANDORIAN WOMEN ARE PERMITTED
ONE FINAL CONQUEST
BEFORE THEIR WEDDING.
I'VE NEVER HAD RELATIONS
WITH A MEMBER OF YOUR SPECIES.
I WAS HOPING YOU'D INDULGE ME.
GO BACK TO YOUR QUARTERS.
YOU WON'T EVEN CONSIDER IT?
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT IS IT?
THERE'S A PROBLEM WITH ONE
OF THE LIQUID FUEL TANKS.
ANOTHER MALFUNCTION?
NO.
THE STARBOARD TRANSFER VALVE
HAS BEEN OPENED -- MANUALLY.
ACTIVATE INTERNAL SENSORS.
[ SIGHS ]
HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
A LITTLE LIGHT-HEADED.
THAT'S NOTHING NEW.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN BETTER.
ABOUT WHAT?
GETTING INVOLVED
WITH A FELLOW OFFICER.
THERE'S NOTHING GOING ON
BETWEEN US ANYMORE,
IF YOU'RE INTERESTED.
THAT'S NOT WHY I ASKED.
WELL, YOU SAID SHE HAD
AN AWFULLY NICE BUM.
THIS IS TRUE.
PURE OXYGEN.
BE MY GUEST.
[ SIGHING ]
THANKS.
HOLD.
MAGNIFY THAT IMAGE.
HUMANS.
IF THEY MAKE THEIR WAY
TO THE BRIDGE...
ARE THE INERTIAL STABILIZERS
OFFLINE?
THEY ARE.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
[ GRUNTING ]
MAGNETIZE YOUR BOOTS.
WE MUSTN'T BE -- WHAT IS THIS?
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GASPING ]
I WANT TO KNOW WHY
MY SHIP WAS ATTACKED.
AND THEN YOU'RE
GOING TO ANSWER
FOR YOUR CRIMES
AGAINST MY PEOPLE.
WHAT DID YOU FIND?
WE'VE DISCOVERED THE FUNCTION
OF THE EMITTERS ON THEIR HULL.
THEY'RE
HOLOGRAPHIC PROJECTORS.
IT'S A CAMOUFLAGE SYSTEM.
THEY CAN USE IT TO MIMIC THE
APPEARANCE OF ALMOST ANY SHIP.
MALCOLM ANALYZED
THE ANDORIAN DEBRIS.
HE SAID THAT SHIP WAS DESTROYED
BY TELLARITE WEAPONS.
THEIR DISRUPTOR UTILIZES
TRI-PHASIC EMITTERS.
[ BEEPS ]
THEY CAN SIMULATE DIFFERENT
KINDS OF WEAPONS.
THE ONE THING THEY COULDN'T MASK
IS THEIR POWER SIGNATURE.
THAT'S WHY --
Security to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
THERE'S WEAPONS FIRE ON G-DECK,
OUTSIDE
THE TELLARITES' QUARTERS.
ON MY WAY.
GET THE MACOs DOWN THERE.
SEAL OFF G-DECK.
WE KNOW YOUR GOVERNMENT'S
BEHIND THE DISAPPEARANCE
OF OUR FREIGHTERS.
WE HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH THAT!
YOU MAY HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO CONVINCE ARCHER,
BUT I'M NOT SO GULLIBLE.
I DON'T KNOW A LOT
ABOUT STARFLEET WEAPONS,
BUT I BELIEVE THIS SETTING
WILL BORE RIGHT THROUGH
THAT THICK HIDE OF YOURS.
THE TRUTH -- NOW!
[ GASPS ]
-COVER!
-GO!
STAY OUT OF THIS, PINK-SKIN.
SHRAN, LISTEN TO ME.
THE SHIP THAT ATTACKED YOU
WASN'T TELLARITE.
[ SCOFFS ]
I WAS THERE!
I CAN PROVE
IT WAS SOMEONE ELSE.
YOU'RE BOTH BEING SET UP.
YOUR SHIP WAS ATTACKED
BECAUSE SOMEONE
DIDN'T WANT THIS CONFERENCE
TO GO FORWARD.
WHO?
I'M ASKING YOU...
ONE CAPTAIN TO ANOTHER...
LOOK AT THE EVIDENCE
BEFORE YOU DO SOMETHING
YOU'RE GONNA REGRET.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GASPING ]
GET PHLOX DOWN HERE.
HOW BAD?
IT'S ONLY SUPERFICIAL.
YOU'LL BE FINE.
The bridge should be
through there!
[ RUMBLING ]
THEY'VE ENTERED THE BRIDGE.