PREVIOUSLY ON
"ENTERPRISE"...
I'M STARTING TO WONDER IF
THIS SHIP EVEN HAS LIFE SUPPORT.
THEY MUST HAVE ATMOSPHERE
ON THEIR BRIDGE.
THE HUMANS HAVE SEEN TOO MUCH.
WE CAN'T ALLOW THEM TO ESCAPE.
[ BOTH GRUNT ]
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
GET OUR PEOPLE BACK.
-DID WE GET EVERYONE?
-JUST THE MACOs.
Trip, we've lost
the transporter.
Sit tight
until we come back for you.
UNDERSTOOD.
IF THIS IS A ROMULAN SHIP,
WHY WOULD THEY BE STIRRING UP
TROUBLE SO FAR FROM HOME?
STAY OUT OF THIS, PINK-SKIN.
SHRAN, LISTEN TO ME.
THE SHIP THAT ATTACKED YOU
WASN'T TELLARITE.
YOU'RE BOTH BEING SET UP.
SOMEONE DIDN'T WANT
THIS CONFERENCE TO GO FORWARD.
THEY'VE ENTERED THE BRIDGE.
THERE'S NO ONE HERE.
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
THEY WON'T LAST MUCH LONGER.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
IT WILL HAVE TO WAIT.
WE'RE APPROACHING
OUR NEXT TARGET.
STABILIZE THE DRONE
FOR BATTLE.
ACTIVATING
THE HOLOGRAPHIC SKIN.
USE THIS CONFIGURATION.
YOU STILL IN ONE PIECE?
YEAH, I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN MY HEAD STOPS SPINNING.
[ ENGINES WHOOSH ]
FEEL THAT?
WE'RE DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
TARGET ACQUIRED.
ENGAGE VISUAL SENSORS.
THE RIGELIANS ARE HAILING US.
ANSWER THEM.
-[ WEAPONS FIRE ]
-WE'RE FIRING AT SOMEONE.
WELL, BRACE YOURSELF.
WHOEVER IT IS,
THEY'LL BE SURE TO FIRE BACK.
THE DRONE IS TAKING DAMAGE.
GIVE THE RIGELIANS TIME
TO SEND THEIR DISTRESS CALL.
NOW, DESTROY THEM.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
FOR NOW, THE TRUCE
BETWEEN THE ANDORIANS
AND TELLARITES
ON ENTERPRISE IS HOLDING.
BUT STARFLEET HAS INFORMED ME
OF A NEW DIPLOMATIC CRISIS.
IT WAS A HEAVILY ARMED
SCOUT SHIP WITH A CREW OF 17.
THERE WERE NO SURVIVORS.
WHY DOES STARFLEET THINK
THIS IS CONNECTED
TO THE OTHER INCIDENTS?
RIGELIANS TRANSMITTED
A VISUAL RECORD
OF THE SHIP
THAT ATTACKED THEM.
I'M TOLD
THEIR TRADE COMMISSION
IS DEMANDING COMPENSATION
AND MY ARREST.
WHOEVER'S BEHIND
THESE ATTACKS,
THEY'RE TRYING TO DO
MORE THAN PROVOKE
A WAR BETWEEN
ANDORIANS AND TELLARITES.
THIS IS AN ATTEMPT TO
DESTABILIZE THE ENTIRE REGION.
WE NEED TO FIND THE MARAUDER
BEFORE IT ATTACKS AGAIN.
I'VE FOUND A WAY TO DETECT
THEIR WARP SIGNATURE.
AND TRAVIS
DESIGNED A SENSOR GRID
THAT SHOULD EXTEND OUR RANGE.
HOW MANY SHIPS WILL IT TAKE
TO MAKE THIS WORK?
ONLY 128.
THERE'S JUST ONE WAY WE CAN GET
THAT MANY SHIPS TO HELP US.
TALAS.
HAVE YOU COME
TO TAKE ME HOME?
I THINK THIS DENOBULAN DOCTOR
IS SECRETLY IN LOVE WITH YOU.
HE WANTS TO KEEP YOU TO HIMSELF.
YOU SAID MY WOUND
WAS SUPERFICIAL.
YOU WERE ONLY GRAZED,
BUT THE PHASE PISTOL
WAS SET TO KILL.
THAT TELLARITE PIG.
IS THERE ANY OTHER KIND?
I'VE SEEN WHAT PHASE-PULSE
INFECTION CAN DO TO ANDORIANS.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
WE'LL BE HOME SOON,
THE TWO OF US.
DON'T LET ME DIE UNAVENGED.
I WON'T.
I'M SORRY. SHE NEEDS TO REST.
YOU SEE WHAT I MEAN?
HE CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF YOU.
I'M JEALOUS.
DOCTOR.
HOW IS SHE?
LUCKY TO BE ALIVE.
I HAVE A PROPOSAL.
IF IT INVOLVES KILLING
TELLARITES, I'M ALL FOR IT.
YOUR SHIP IS ADRIFT
IN ENEMY SPACE,
DAMAGED AND DEFENSELESS,
BECAUSE OF A SINGLE
RIGELIAN SCOUT SHIP?
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT ME
TO REPORT TO THE SENATE?
THE DRONE
HAS TAKEN DAMAGE BEFORE.
IT'S DESIGNED TO SELF-REPAIR.
IF OUR ENEMIES FIND IT --
THAT'S THE POINT
OF THIS PROJECT.
NO PRISONERS TO CAPTURE,
NO BODIES TO RECOVER.
THESE DRONE SHIPS CAN NEVER
BE TRACED BACK TO US.
THIS PROTOTYPE'S
A MODIFIED WARBIRD.
THE VULCANS WOULD IDENTIFY IT
THE MOMENT THEY INSPECTED
THE PROPULSION MATRIX.
THE VULCANS WON'T
GET ANYWHERE NEAR IT.
DON'T UNDERESTIMATE
OUR DISTANT BROTHERS.
BRING YOUR SHIP HOME.
I'LL TELL THE SENATE THAT
YOUR TEST HAS BEEN A SUCCESS.
OTHERWISE, THEY'LL MAKE SOMEONE
PAY FOR THIS FAILURE.
AND I PROMISE YOU,
IT WON'T BE ME.
JOLAN TRU, ADMIRAL.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
ADMIRAL GARDNER JUST CALLED.
HE'S SENDING EVERY SHIP
AVAILABLE, BUT AT TOP SPEED,
IT'LL TAKE WEEKS
FOR MOST OF THEM TO GET HERE.
WHAT ABOUT COLUMBIA?
SHE'S STUCK IN DRY DOCK --
ENGINE TROUBLE.
DID YOU GET THROUGH
TO YOUR PEOPLE?
MINISTER T'PAU IS
DISPATCHING 23 VESSELS.
THAT'S ALL?
THE HIGH COMMAND
HAS BEEN DISBANDED.
MANY OF OUR SHIPS NO LONGER
HAVE FULL CREW COMPLEMENTS.
T'PAU COULD HAVE PICKED
A BETTER TIME TO CLEAN HOUSE.
ANDORIAN AND TELLARITE
FLEET DEPLOYMENTS?
I'M THINKING OF ASKING THEM
TO JOIN US.
WITHOUT MORE SHIPS, OUR SENSOR
NET'S GONNA HAVE A GAPING HOLE.
THE MARAUDER COULD FLY RIGHT
THROUGH IT, AND WE'D NEVER KNOW.
HAVE YOU DISCUSSED THIS
WITH COMMANDER SHRAN
OR AMBASSADOR GRAL?
NOT YET.
EVEN IF BOTH SIDES WERE TO
AGREE, WHICH SEEMS UNLIKELY,
THEIR DEPLOYMENTS
WOULD HAVE TO BE COORDINATED,
A COMMAND HIERARCHY
ESTABLISHED.
AN ANDORIAN CAPTAIN
MIGHT HAVE A PROBLEM
-TAKING ORDERS FROM
A TELLARITE?
-PRECISELY.
THERE'S ONE SPECIES
THAT'S ON FRIENDLY TERMS
WITH BOTH OF THEM -- HUMANS.
ENTERPRISE COULD SERVE
AS THE COMMAND SHIP,
RELAYING ALL ORDERS.
THE OTHER SHIPS
WOULD ONLY HAVE
TO EXCHANGE
COMMUNICATION CODES.
IT MIGHT WORK.
YOU DON'T SOUND
TOO OPTIMISTIC.
THESE FOUR SPECIES HAVE NEVER
COOPERATED ON A MUTUAL ENDEAVOR.
AS FAR AS I KNOW,
NO ONE'S EVER TRIED
TO GET THEM TOGETHER BEFORE.
FROM WHAT I'VE HEARD ABOUT THESE
ROMULANS, THEY MEAN BUSINESS.
IF THEY'RE BEHIND THESE ATTACKS,
WE HAVE TO FIND SOME WAY
TO STOP THEM,
OR NEXT TIME,
THEY MIGHT COME BACK
WITH A THOUSAND OF THOSE SHIPS.
SOME OF THESE CIRCUITS
ARE LIVE,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE FOR.
I CAN'T FIGURE OUT
WHAT HALF THIS STUFF IS.
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHER HALF?
WELL, I THINK I FOUND
AN ENVIRONMENTAL SYSTEM.
THAT'D MAKE SENSE.
THESE CONSOLES LOOK
LIKE CREW STATIONS.
HERE GOES.
WELL, HOW ABOUT THAT?
IN A FEW MINUTES,
WE'LL HAVE HEAT AND AIR.
AH.
DO YOU THINK IT'S POSSIBLE THAT
THERE'S NO ONE ELSE ONBOARD?
WHY WOULD A ROBOT SHIP
HAVE A BRIDGE LIKE THIS?
IT COULD BE A PROTOTYPE --
OUTFIT AN EXISTING SHIP WITH
THE LATEST IN COMPUTER CONTROLS.
WELL, THAT'D MAKE THINGS
A WHOLE LOT EASIER FOR US.
HOW'S THAT?
IF THIS SHIP'S RUN BY COMPUTER,
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS
FIND THE OFF SWITCH.
AH.
I'D RATHER COHABIT
WITH KLINGON TARGS
THAN JOIN FORCES
WITH TELLARITES!
YOUR PERSONAL MATING PREFERENCE
IS NO CONCERN OF MINE.
IF YOU'RE WAITING FOR ME
TO STOP YOU, DON'T WORRY.
I WON'T.
YOU HEARD WHAT HE SAID!
AND I HEARD WHAT YOU SAID.
SO NOW IT'S TIME FOR BOTH
OF YOU TO LISTEN TO ME.
INSTEAD OF INSULTING YOU
TO MAKE YOU FEEL AT HOME
AND PUTTING UP
WITH YOUR ARROGANCE
AS A SIGN OF MY RESPECT,
WHY DON'T THE TWO OF YOU TRY
BEHAVING LIKE HUMANS
FOR A CHANGE?
AND YOU SAID YOU WOULDN'T
BE INSULTING?
THERE'S ONE THING
HUMANS SEEM TO DO BETTER
THAN ANY SPECIES WE'VE MET.
WHEN WE'RE FACED
WITH A COMMON THREAT,
WE PUT OUR DIFFERENCES ASIDE
AND TRY TO COOPERATE.
SOMEONE IS DETERMINED TO START
A WAR IN THIS REGION.
I'VE SHOWN YOU
HOW WE CAN STOP THEM.
BUT IF YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND THAT,
FEEL FREE TO STRANGLE
EACH OTHER.
JUST REMEMBER,
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT
THIS MARAUDER WANTS YOU TO DO.
WE'VE GONE BACK TO WARP.
AND JUST WHEN IT HAPPENED,
I GOT A POWER SPIKE
FROM ONE OF THESE CONDUITS.
DO YOU THINK WARP CONTROL
RUNS THROUGH HERE?
IF THIS SHIP WAS
ORIGINALLY BUILT FOR A CREW,
ALL OF ITS CONTROLS
SHOULD CONNECT TO THE BRIDGE.
MAYBE THEY NEVER
GOT DISCONNECTED.
KEEP YOUR EYES
ON THESE CONSOLES.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
DID YOU DO THAT?
EVEN MONEY WE JUST FOUND
THE PROPULSION CONTROLS.
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
I CAN'T TELL FOR SURE.
VISUAL SURVEILLANCE IS OFFLINE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THE DRONE IS
DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
[ ENGINE WHOOSHES ]
YOU FOUND THE OFF SWITCH?
ALL I DID WAS INTERRUPT
THE POWER TO THE WARP CONTROLS.
THERE'S PROBABLY A BACKUP THAT
WILL SWITCH ON IN A FEW MINUTES.
CAN YOU MAKE
ANY SENSE OF THIS?
AH, WHERE'S HOSHI
WHEN YOU NEED HER?
THAT'S WHERE WE ARE.
I'M GONNA GUESS THAT'S THE POWER
CIRCUIT I JUST SHUT DOWN.
IF THIS WERE ENTERPRISE,
THAT'D BE THE POWER COUPLING FOR
THE ENTIRE WARP-CONTROL SYSTEM,
INCLUDING THE BACKUPS.
SHOULD BE RIGHT THROUGH THERE.
HUH. MAESTRO.
ONE OF THEM'S LEFT THE BRIDGE.
HE'S IN THE SERVICE JUNCTION.
WHY?
IT APPEARS HE'S LOCATED THE MAIN
COUPLING FOR THE WARP MATRIX.
WHAT ELSE IS IN THERE?
JUST WHAT WE NEED TO KILL HIM.
OKAY, MALCOLM.
I'M GONNA FLIP THROUGH THESE,
LIKE, CIRCUIT BREAKERS.
LET ME KNOW
HOW THE DIAGRAM CHANGES.
READY WHEN YOU ARE.
THERE'S THE FIRST ONE.
-IT WENT OUT.
-HE'S DISABLING
THE WARP SYSTEM.
IS SELF-REPAIR
STILL ACTIVATED?
IT'LL TAKE MORE THAN A DAY
TO REROUTE THE MAJOR CIRCUITS.
WE DON'T HAVE A DAY.
ONE OF THEM IS STILL
IN THE SERVICE JUNCTION.
SEAL HIM IN.
I'M GONNA SEE IF THERE'S
A COMMUNICATIONS CIRCUIT
WE CAN TAP INTO.
MALCOLM!
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
MALCOLM,
DID YOU TOUCH SOMETHING?
WASN'T ME.
DO THE HATCH CONTROLS
WORK ON YOUR SIDE?
NEGATIVE.
THEY'RE NOT RESPONDING.
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
Listen carefully,
and you won't be harmed.
-WHO ARE YOU?
-I CONTROL THE SHIP.
NOT ANYMORE, YOU DON'T.
COMMANDER, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
REACTOR COOLANT.
RADIATION'S AT 100 ROENTGENS
AND CLIMBING.
That gives you seven minutes,
Commander.
Reestablish the warp matrix,
or you will die.
COMPLIMENTS
OF THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
THESE ARE
THE COMMUNICATION CODES
WE'LL USE FOR
THE JOINT OPERATION.
GRAL'S INFORMED ME THAT THE
TELLARITES ARE ALSO TAKING PART.
SO THEY'LL NEED
THESE CODES AS WELL.
DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO.
I APPRECIATE YOUR COOPERATION.
YOU'RE NOT ESPECIALLY DIFFICULT
TO WORK WITH, CAPTAIN.
UNLIKE TELLARITES,
YOU UNDERSTAND ETHICS
AND TRY TO LIVE BY THEM.
TRY?
WELL, NOBODY'S PERFECT.
HAVE YOU SERVED ON
ALL THESE VESSELS?
A FEW OF THEM ARE
A BIT BEFORE MY TIME.
BUT THEY WERE ALL
NAMED ENTERPRISE.
THIS ONE SAILED EARTH'S OCEANS
ALMOST 400 YEARS AGO.
MY VESSEL, THE KUMARI,
WAS NAMED
FOR THE FIRST ICE-CUTTER
TO CIRCUMNAVIGATE ANDORIA.
PERHAPS FUTURE SHIPS WILL
BE NAMED AFTER OUR VESSELS,
ESPECIALLY IF WE DO
SOMETHING HISTORIC TOGETHER.
THERE'S NO REASON OUR PEOPLE
CAN'T BECOME ALLIES.
AGREED.
PAY ATTENTION
TO THAT BOARD, MALCOLM.
I'M GONNA TRY TO CUT POWER
TO THE REACTOR.
I'VE GOT A BETTER IDEA.
MAKE SURE YOU'RE WELL AWAY
FROM THE DOOR.
YOU'RE WASTING TIME, COMMANDER.
THE RADIATION WILL BE FATAL
IN THREE MINUTES.
I can save you.
MALCOLM,
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE BOARD?
EVERYTHING'S OFF.
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
RADIATION'S FALLING.
THEY'VE TAKEN
THE REACTOR OFFLINE.
ACTIVATE THE BACKUP SEQUENCER.
I'm still in control.
There's nothing you can do
to save your life
EXCEPT FOLLOW MY INSTRUCTIONS.
WE'VE RECEIVED
THE FINAL CONFIRMATIONS.
ALL 128 SHIPS ARE IN POSITION.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-Phlox to Captain Archer.
GO AHEAD.
I require you in sick bay
as soon as possible.
NO.
I DID EVERYTHING I COULD.
YOU SAID SHE'D RECOVER.
SHRAN.
[ SIGHS ]
[ SOBBING ]
NO.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Commander, what's your status?
I SHOULD HAVE BROUGHT MY HELMET.
RADIATION'S AT 180 AND CLIMBING.
I CAN'T SHUT IT DOWN.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO DIE LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE NOT GETTING
THIS SHIP BACK.
You're wrong, Commander.
EVENTUALLY
IT WILL REPAIR ITSELF.
YOU'LL HAVE DIED FOR NOTHING.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL RECONNECT THE MATRIX.
OPEN THE HATCH!
MALCOLM, NO!
THAT'S AN ORDER!
[ PANTING ]
COMMANDER?
Do your duty, Malcolm.
RESTORE THE MATRIX.
SAVE YOUR COMMANDER'S LIFE.
THERE! EVERY TELLARITE SHIP IS
CONNECTED TO YOUR SENSOR NETWORK
DESPITE THE INEFFICIENT
ANDORIAN CODES.
NOW COMES THE HARD PART.
WE HAVE TO SIT AND WAIT.
WE'RE NOT A PATIENT PEOPLE.
I'VE NOTICED.
-MAYBE THAT'S
SOMETHING WE CAN --
-[ DOOR OPENS ]
I ONLY WANT TO TALK TO HIM!
I ONLY WANT TO TALK.
WE'RE LISTENING.
YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT TALAS,
THE WOMAN YOU KILLED.
SHE ATTACKED US.
THE ATTACK WAS OVER
WHEN YOU SHOT HER.
BUT I'M NOT HERE
TO ARGUE THAT.
HER FAMILY WAS PRIVILEGED,
HER PARENTS WEALTHY.
SHE COULD HAVE CHOSEN
ANY CAREER,
NEVER KNOWN DISCOMFORT.
BUT SHE FELT THE CALL OF DUTY.
SHE PLEDGED HER LIFE
TO THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
TALAS COULD HAVE HAD ANYTHING.
ANYONE.
SHE CHOSE ME.
I JUST WANTED YOU TO KNOW.
IT'S HER BLOOD.
WHEN A GUARDSMAN
DIES FAR FROM HOME,
HIS COMPANIONS --
HER COMPANIONS --
CARRY A PART OF HER
BACK TO THE ICE
OF ANDORIA.
I WANTED YOU
TO KNOW THAT, TOO...
...BEFORE YOU DIE!
THAT'S ENOUGH!
NOT UNTIL HIS BLOOD
PAYS FOR HERS!
KEEP HIM AWAY!
YOU WILL FACE JUSTICE
AT MY HANDS!
THAT'S NOT GONNA
HAPPEN ON MY SHIP.
YES, IT WILL, PINK-SKIN,
BECAUSE IF YOU
AND THE TELLARITES
DON'T SHOW RESPECT
FOR ANDORIAN TRADITION,
THE IMPERIAL GUARD
WILL WITHDRAW ITS SHIPS.
WHAT TRADITION?
UNLESS THIS MURDERER
MEETS ME IN COMBAT,
YOUR PRECIOUS ALLIANCE
IS FINISHED!
I'M RECONNECTING
THE WARP MATRIX!
Shut off the radiation!
WHEN YOU'RE FINISHED.
THERE!
NOW SHUT IT OFF!
AND OPEN THIS HATCH!
COMMANDER, STAY WITH ME.
THE MATRIX HAS
BEEN REACTIVATED.
THEN WE DON'T NEED
THE HUMANS ANYMORE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU LISTEN TO ME?
WE'RE BETTER OFF HERE
THAN ON THE BRIDGE.
[ BEEPING ]
TAKE IT TO WARP.
SET A COURSE FOR HOME.
[ ENGINE WHOOSHES ]
WE'RE BACK AT WARP.
I ORDERED YOU
NOT TO HELP THEM.
I APOLOGIZE FOR SAVING
YOUR LIFE, COMMANDER.
IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
SORRY.
ACCORDING
TO THE BRIDGE SCHEMATIC,
THIS IS AN ACCESS PANEL.
WHERE DOES IT LEAD?
AWAY FROM THE BRIDGE.
WHAT DOES THAT GIVE US?
WE SHOULD ASSUME
THAT WE'RE BEING MONITORED.
DID YOU EVER READ THE MANUAL
THAT CAME WITH THAT THING?
THE WARNING ABOUT
INADVERTENT OVERLOAD.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE?
BY NOW, LESS THAN A MINUTE.
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT ACCESS PANEL
ARE THEY TALKING ABOUT?
IT LEADS INTO
THE SUPERSTRUCTURE,
AWAY FROM ANY
CRITICAL EQUIPMENT.
WE'LL DEAL WITH THEM
WHEN THE DRONE RETURNS.
WE'VE GOT TO BE
A SAFE DISTANCE BY NOW.
I WIRED IT DIRECTLY
INTO THE POWER CONDUIT.
WE'VE LOST CONTACT.
THE ANDORIAN TRADITION
SHRAN WANTS TO FOLLOW
IS CALLED THE USHAAN.
BASICALLY,
IT'S A DUEL TO THE DEATH.
THE COMBATANTS
FIGHT WITH THESE.
IT'S CALLED A USHAAN-TOR.
IT'S AN ICE-MINER'S TOOL.
ANDORIANS PLAY
WITH THEM AS CHILDREN.
A TELLARITE WON'T STAND A CHANCE
USING ONE AGAINST SHRAN.
I DON'T THINK
THAT'S GONNA BE AN ISSUE.
AMBASSADOR GRAL'S REFUSING
TO LET NAARG FIGHT.
ANDORIANS WILL CONSIDER THAT
A FURTHER INSULT.
WHAT ELSE DO WE KNOW
ABOUT THIS TRADITION?
PLEASE, MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME.
AN OLD FRIEND --
I CARRY IT EVERYWHERE.
TWO HOURS AGO, WE SPOKE
ABOUT A NEW PARTNERSHIP
BETWEEN ANDORIA AND EARTH.
A BENEFIT TO BOTH OUR WORLDS.
YOU'RE THROWING IT AWAY
FOR PERSONAL VENGEANCE.
THERE'S MORE TO THIS THAN TALAS.
I LOST MY SHIP,
ALMOST MY ENTIRE CREW.
IF I DO NOTHING TO
AVENGE THESE LOSSES,
WHAT KIND OF A LEADER AM I?
WHY SHOULD ANY SOLDIER
FOLLOW ME AGAIN?
BESIDES, YOU SHOULD
BE WISHING ME LUCK.
I PROVIDE A VOICE FOR YOUR
SPECIES AT THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
I'M VALUABLE TO HUMANS.
I SPOKE TO AMBASSADOR GRAL
ABOUT THE RULES
OF THE USHAAN...
SPECIFICALLY,
THE RIGHT OF SUBSTITUTION.
THE AMBASSADOR'S DECIDED TO
FIGHT IN PLACE OF HIS UNDERLING?
NOT THE AMBASSADOR.
YOU WOULDN'T.
I'M THE SUBSTITUTE.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO FIGHT ME.
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO KILL YOU.
YOU'RE MY FRIEND.
THEN CALL IT OFF.
I CAN'T.
YOU DID ALL THIS
WITH ONE PHASE PISTOL?
YOU'RE GOOD AT BUILDING THINGS.
I'M GOOD AT BLOWING THEM UP.
I'M THINKING WE SHOULD
GET TO THE OUTER HULL.
NO, WE MIGHT BE SAFER FINDING
ANOTHER AREA WITH LIFE SUPPORT.
THE HULL'S COVERED
WITH SUBSPACE TRANSCEIVERS.
IF I CAN LINK ONE OF THEM
TO OUR COMMUNICATORS,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO
CONTACT ENTERPRISE.
ADMIRAL, THE DRONE'S
RESTORED CONTACT.
THE REPAIR SYSTEMS
ARE STARTING TO WORK.
IT WILL TAKE DAYS.
LET ME KNOW WHEN IT'S RESTORED
ITS ABILITY TO SELF-DESTRUCT.
-[ DOOR CHIMES ]
-COME IN.
UPDATING YOUR WILL?
YOU EXPECT ME TO LOSE?
SHRAN IS A MEMBER
OF THE IMPERIAL GUARD,
TRAINED IN COMBAT
FROM CHILDHOOD.
HE WON'T BACK DOWN.
HE CAN'T. I UNDERSTAND.
IF YOU BACK DOWN, THE IMPERIAL
GUARD WILL WITHDRAW THEIR SHIPS.
IF I KILL SHRAN, OR ONE
OF THE TELLARITES DOES,
THE ANDORIANS
WILL PULL OUT ANYWAY.
THE TELLARITES
WILL DO THE SAME THING
IF SHRAN KILLS ONE OF THEM.
SO...I'M THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN BE KILLED,
BECAUSE STARFLEET
WON'T WITHDRAW.
THIS OPERATION IS IMPORTANT,
CONSIDERING THAT IT MIGHT LEAD
TO AN ALLIANCE OF PLANETS.
VULCANS HAVE A SAYING --
ONE MAN CAN SUMMON THE FUTURE.
WHAT HAPPENS IF THAT MAN
THROWS AWAY HIS LIFE
BEFORE HIS TIME?
IF I'VE LEARNED ANYTHING THESE
PAST FEW YEARS ON ENTERPRISE,
IT'S THAT THE FUTURE
ISN'T FIXED.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS TO YOU...
THEN I'D BETTER MAKE SURE
THAT NOTHING DOES.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
DIDN'T EXPECT TO
FIND YOU UP THIS LATE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
TOO WIRED TO SLEEP.
HARD TO BELIEVE
THE CAPTAIN'S GONNA BE
FIGHTING A DUEL TO THE DEATH
IN A FEW HOURS.
BARBARIC, IF YOU ASK ME.
-WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING AT?
-THE CODE OF THE USHAAN.
T'POL WANTS ME TO
GO OVER IT AGAIN,
SEE IF I CAN FIND
A WAY OUT OF THIS MESS.
WELL, THE LAST I HEARD,
THE CAPTAIN SOUNDED DETERMINED
TO GO THROUGH WITH IT.
SHE WANTS ME TO FIND
A LOOPHOLE,
SOME WAY TO FORFEIT WITHOUT
OFFENDING THE ANDORIANS.
TWO OF US COULD GET THROUGH
THAT A LOT FASTER.
LOOK AT THIS.
EITHER COMBATANT
CAN POSTPONE A DUEL INDEFINITELY
IF THERE ARE NO CHILDREN
TO CONTINUE HIS CLAN.
HOW DOES THAT HELP US?
AS FAR AS I KNOW, CAPTAIN ARCHER
DOESN'T HAVE ANY KIDS.
IF HE'S KILLED,
HIS CLAN WOULD DIE WITH HIM.
THAT RULE ONLY APPLIES
IF HE'S MARRIED.
DON'T SUPPOSE WE CAN FIND HIM
A WIFE IN THE NEXT FOUR HOURS.
EVEN IF WE COULD,
SOMETHING TELLS ME
THE ANDORIANS WOULD CRY FOUL.
[ SIGHS ]
THERE ARE 12,000 AMENDMENTS
TO THIS RIDICULOUS HONOR CODE.
THERE'S GOT TO BE ONE
THAT CAN GET HIM OUT OF THIS.
INSTEAD OF LOOKING
FOR A LOOPHOLE,
MAYBE WE SHOULD BE TRYING
TO FIND A WAY
FOR THE CAPTAIN TO WIN.
IF THE CAPTAIN WINS,
SHRAN'S DEAD.
THE ALLIANCE FALLS APART.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
TO NOBELIA PRIME?
NOT RECENTLY.
THE TRIBAL ELDERS THERE --
THEY CAN
CHALLENGE YOU TO A DUEL
IF YOU LOOK AT THEM
THE WRONG WAY.
HAPPENED TO MY FATHER.
HOW DID HE GET OUT OF IT?
WHICH ONE OF THESE
HAS THE COMBAT RULES?
DON'T TRY AND BLOCK WITH THIS.
WHEN HE SWINGS, INTERCEPT,
DEFLECT, AND HOOK IT AWAY.
BETTER TO INSERT
BETWEEN THE EYES AND TWIST.
ANDORIAN METABOLISM
IS HIGHER THAN HUMANS'.
KEEP MOVING,
YOU'LL EXHAUST HIM.
HOW ABOUT I JUST WIN?
TAKE YOUR PLACES.
THERE IS STILL TIME
TO END THIS.
IT CAN ONLY END ONE WAY.
THIS IS NOT WHAT I WANTED.
THINGS HAVE A WAY OF TURNING OUT
DIFFERENTLY THAN WE EXPECT.
I'M GLAD WE MET.
IN YOUR HONOR, I'LL CONTINUE
TO SUPPORT COOPERATION
BETWEEN THE IMPERIAL GUARD
AND YOUR SPECIES.
LET'S GET THIS OVER WITH.
I GOT A SHIP TO RUN.
I'LL TAKE YOUR BLOOD
TO ANDORIA...
TO THE WALL OF HEROES.
NOT TODAY.
YOU HAVE THE FIRST MOVE.
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
GIVE UP.
A SINGLE STROKE,
AND THERE'LL BE NO PAIN.
YOU THINK I'M LOSING?
I'M JUST TRYING TO MAKE YOU LOOK
GOOD IN FRONT OF YOUR SOLDIERS.
NOW DO YOU GIVE UP?
NEVER!
WRONG CHOICE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
CUT OFF MY HEAD!
I CONSIDERED IT,
BUT I STILL NEED YOUR HELP.
[ GROANING ]
WHAT GOOD IS A GUARDSMAN
WITHOUT TWO ANTENNAE?
UGH.
YOU'LL BEGIN TO COMPENSATE
WITHIN A DAY OR TWO.
THEY TAKE NINE MONTHS
TO GROW BACK.
IF LEFT UNTREATED.
WITH ELECTRICAL STIMULATION
AND BRISK CRANIAL MASSAGE,
YOU'LL BE BACK TO NORMAL
IN HALF THAT TIME.
I WAS TOLD THAT THE LOSS
OF AN ANTENNA WASN'T CRITICAL...
YOU HUMILIATED ME.
...AND THAT THE USHAAN
IS SETTLED
WHEN ONE FIGHTER IS
RENDERED DEFENSELESS.
ARE WE DONE?
YOU RESPECTED
ANDORIAN TRADITION.
IT'S SETTLED.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-Bridge to Captain Archer.
FOUR SHIPS HAVE LOCATED
THE MARAUDER'S POWER SIGNATURE.
CAN YOU PICK UP BIO-SIGNS?
NOT AT THIS DISTANCE.
TRAVIS,
PLOT AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
TAKE US TO MAXIMUM WARP.
INTERCEPT IN 47 MINUTES.
ALERT THE FLEET.
THE DRONE'S SENSORS
HAVE DETECTED ENTERPRISE.
IT'S CLOSING.
ACTIVATE THE HOLOGRAPHIC SKIN.
SOMETHING'S STARTING TO DRAW
A LOT OF POWER.
IT'S ALL THE SYSTEMS THAT
WENT DOWN IN THE EXPLOSION.
THEY'RE COMING BACK ONLINE.
-WHAT ABOUT THE WARP MATRIX?
-NOT YET.
BUT IF WE WANT TO CONTACT
ENTERPRISE, WE'D BETTER HURRY.
APPROACHING VISUAL RANGE.
ON SCREEN.
MAGNIFY.
VULCAN?
CHECK THEIR POWER SIGNATURE.
IT DOESN'T MATCH.
TACTICAL ALERT.
CHARGE WEAPONS.
ENTERPRISE WILL REACH THE DRONE
BEFORE THE MATRIX IS RESTORED.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
SENATOR,
I WAS NOT TOLD OF YOUR VISIT.
YOU ALLOWED OUR ENEMIES TO
BOARD AND DISABLE THE DRONE.
I HAVE MY SOURCES, ADMIRAL.
THEN YOU KNOW WE ARE ABOUT
TO ENGAGE THE HUMAN SHIP.
I'M HERE TO WITNESS
ITS DESTRUCTION.
ONE MINUTE.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
-WE HAVE BIO-SIGNS.
TWO HUMANS.
CAN YOU GET
A TRANSPORTER LOCK?
WE'LL NEED TO BE MUCH CLOSER.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
ARCHER TO TUCKER AND REED.
RESPOND.
We're both here, Captain.
[ SIGHS ]
FIRE.
TARGET ITS WEAPONS.
I CAN'T GET A LOCK
THROUGH THE CAMOUFLAGE.
TAKE OUT THE EMITTERS,
BUT DON'T PUNCTURE THE HULL.
[ BOTH GRUNT ]
THEY DO KNOW WE'RE ONBOARD?
THEY'RE PROBABLY TRYING
TO TAKE OUT THE WEAPONS.
ENTERPRISE, ANY CHANCE
OF USING THE TRANSPORTER?
YOU HAVE TO GET CLOSER
TO THE HULL.
-Can you do that?
-WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
WE'VE LOST THE EMITTERS.
WARP STATUS?
TWO MINUTES.
MORE ENEMY SHIPS ARE CLOSING.
IF ENTERPRISE STOPS
THE SELF-REPAIR SEQUENCE --
THE DRONE WILL ESCAPE.
ENTERPRISE!
WE'RE AT THE HULL!
THE SHIP'S MOVEMENT IS TOO
ERRATIC. I CAN'T GET A LOCK.
THEY'RE TARGETING
OUR WARP CORE.
HULL PLATING IS AT 43%.
36%.
SHUT DOWN WEAPONS.
ALL POWER TO HULL PLATING.
TRAVIS, BRING US ABOUT.
TRIP, MALCOLM,
WE CAN MAKE ONE MORE PASS.
GET THE HELL OUT OF THERE.
THEIR WEAPONS ARE OFFLINE.
THEY'RE VULNERABLE.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW THINGS
COULD GET MUCH WORSE!
I CAN.
AAH!
THEY'RE CLEAR.
SENSORS ARE DOWN.
I'VE LOST THEM.
SIX MORE ENEMY SHIPS
WITHIN RANGE.
20 SECONDS TO WARP.
WE'VE GOT COMPANY --
ALLIANCE SHIPS.
TELL THEM NOT TO FIRE.
OUR PEOPLE ARE OUT THERE.
THE MATRIX IS RESTORED.
WITHDRAW.
THEY LEFT US.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
THIS IS WORSE.
Anyone out there need a lift?
IF I HAD TO WEAR THIS HELMET
FOR ONE MORE MINUTE,
I SWEAR IT WOULD'VE
FUSED TO MY SKULL.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I TELL YOU, I'D LIKE TO FIND
THE DESIGNER OF THIS SUIT
AND MAKE HIM
WEAR IT FOR THREE DAYS.
YEAH.
THANKS FOR WHAT
YOU DID BACK THERE.
YEAH, YOU WOULD HAVE DONE
THE SAME FOR ME.
NO, YOU TOOK A BIG CHANCE...
WHICH MAKES WHAT I HAVE TO DO
ALL THE MORE DIFFICULT.
I'M PUTTING YOU ON REPORT.
YOU'RE WHAT?
YOU DISOBEYED
A DIRECT ORDER.
I SAVED YOUR LIFE!
IF YOU PUT A REPRIMAND
IN MY FILE,
IT COULD BE YEARS BEFORE
I'M EVEN ELIGIBLE FOR...
[ LAUGHING ]
ARE YOU PULLING MY LEG?
M-MALCOLM, YOU'RE JUST
SUCH AN EASY TARGET.
[ LAUGHING ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
THE MARAUDER GOT AWAY.
ONE OF THE TELLARITE SHIPS
WAS HIT.
AN ANDORIAN WARSHIP
RESCUED THE CREW.
SO IT'S STILL OUT THERE --
AS YOU SAID,
A COMMON THREAT.
I BELIEVE WE HAVE MORE TO
DISCUSS THAN TRADE DISPUTES.
WHY WAIT UNTIL
WE GET TO BABEL?
THE DRONE HAS
REENTERED ROMULAN SPACE.
DISCONNECT THE PILOT.