PREVIOUSLY ON
"ENTERPRISE"...
FROM WHAT I'VE HEARD ABOUT THESE
ROMULANS, THEY MEAN BUSINESS.
WE HAVE TO FIND SOME WAY
TO STOP THEM, OR NEXT TIME,
THEY MIGHT COME BACK WITH
A THOUSAND OF THOSE SHIPS.
UNLESS THIS MURDERER
MEETS ME IN COMBAT,
YOUR PRECIOUS ALLIANCE
IS FINISHED!
THE AMBASSADOR HAS DECIDED TO
FIGHT IN PLACE OF HIS UNDERLING.
NOT THE AMBASSADOR.
[ CHOKING ]
TRIP, MALCOLM,
WE CAN MAKE ONE MORE PASS.
GET THE HELL OUT OF THERE.
THEY'RE CLEAR.
THE DRONE HAS
RE-ENTERED ROMULAN SPACE.
DISCONNECT THE PILOT.
I BELIEVE WE HAVE MORE TO
DISCUSS THAN TRADE DISPUTES.
THERE'S NO REASON OUR PEOPLE
CAN'T BECOME ALLIES.
AND NOW THE CONCLUSION.
THIS MISSION WAS SUPPOSED TO
CAUSE DISSENSION IN THE REGION.
IT'S HAD THE OPPOSITE EFFECT.
SENATOR, YOU HAVE A RIGHT --
THE ANDORIANS AND TELLARITES
HAVE FORMED AN ALLIANCE.
THEY'RE WORKING TOGETHER
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN HISTORY.
IT WON'T LAST.
THE GROUP OF SENATORS
DOESN'T SHARE YOUR OPTIMISM.
THEY'RE PRESENTING A MOTION
TO CANCEL THIS MISSION.
THAT WOULD BE A MISTAKE.
THE MISTAKE WAS MINE WHEN
I SUPPORTED THIS ENDEAVOR.
DO YOU REALIZE HOW YOU'VE
WEAKENED MY POSITION?
WHEN THIS IS OVER,
YOU'LL BE FIRST CONSUL.
AFTER A FAILURE OF THIS
MAGNITUDE, I COULD BE DEAD.
THIS ISN'T A FAILURE.
IT'S A SETBACK.
WE HAVE TO DEAL
WITH THE HUMANS.
THEY'RE THE ONES
THAT BROUGHT THE ANDORIANS
AND TELLARITES TOGETHER.
THE SECOND DRONE SHIP IS ARMED
AND READY FOR BATTLE.
WITH TWO SHIPS, I CAN DELIVER
A DEVASTATING BLOW.
WE WILL HUNT DOWN ENTERPRISE
AND DESTROY IT.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
A TRANSPORT SHIP IS RETURNING
THE TELLARITE AMBASSADOR
TO HIS HOMEWORLD.
BUT SHRAN HAS OFFERED TO STAY
AND HELP US TRACK DOWN
THE MARAUDER.
THE DRONE IS BEING OPERATED
BY TELEPRESENCE.
IT'S A PROCESS
WHICH ALLOWS A VESSEL
TO BE CONTROLLED
FROM A REMOTE LOCATION.
WE EXPERIMENTED
WITH THAT YEARS AGO.
NOTHING CAME OF IT.
A PILOT CAN OPERATE THE DRONE
FROM A GREAT DISTANCE,
OVER MANY LIGHT-YEARS.
SO, THERE REALLY
WAS NO ONE ON THAT SHIP.
AND THE PEOPLE RUNNING IT
ARE BACK ON THEIR HOMEWORLD,
SAFE AND SOUND.
ESSENTIALLY.
DOESN'T SEEM FAIR.
IS THERE ANY WAY TO INTERRUPT
THIS TELEPRESENCE?
I'M STILL REVIEWING THE DATA
COMMANDER TUCKER BROUGHT BACK.
BUT I BELIEVE WE CAN CONSTRUCT
OUR OWN TELEPRESENCE UNIT.
-AND USE IT TO HIJACK
THEIR SHIP?
-DOUBTFUL.
THE MOST WE CAN HOPE FOR IS TO
INTERFERE WITH THEIR NAVIGATION.
-GET STARTED.
-THERE IS ONE PROBLEM.
THE DATA FROM THE MARAUDER ALSO
CONTAINED A BRAIN-WAVE PATTERN.
I BELIEVE IT BELONGS
TO THE PILOT.
I'VE ANALYZED IT.
THE INDIVIDUAL
IS HIGHLY TELEPATHIC.
APPARENTLY, TELEPATHY IS
NECESSARY TO OPERATE THE DEVICE.
VULCANS HAVE
TELEPATHIC POWERS.
NOT TO THIS EXTENT.
CAN YOU IDENTIFY THE SPECIES?
THERE'S NO EXACT MATCH
IN MY DATABASE.
HOWEVER, THE NEAREST GENOME
IS ANDORIAN.
THE HUMANS DID CONSIDERABLE
DAMAGE TO THE BRIDGE.
WE'LL HAVE TO REPLACE
THE ENTIRE RECEIVER ARRAY.
ASSIGN EVERY SPARE MAN
TO THE REPAIR CREW.
THE SHIP ISN'T
WHAT CONCERNS ME.
-IT'S THE PILOT.
-WHAT ABOUT HIM?
OPERATING THE VESSEL
IS EXTREMELY TAXING.
HE'LL HAVE AT LEAST
THREE DAYS TO REST.
THAT WON'T BE ENOUGH.
HE'S SUFFERING FROM
SEVERE MENTAL FATIGUE.
PILOTING ONE SHIP WOULD BE
DIFFICULT ENOUGH, BUT TWO...
THEN YOU'LL HAVE TO
INCREASE THE STIMULANTS.
THE DOSAGE IS ALREADY
AT A DANGEROUS LEVEL.
HE COULD BE PERMANENTLY DAMAGED.
HE COULD DIE.
IF I DIDN'T KNOW YOU BETTER,
I'D SAY YOU'RE MORE CONCERNED
WITH THIS CREATURE'S WELL-BEING
THAN YOU ARE WITH THIS MISSION.
WITHOUT THE PILOT,
THERE WOULD BE NO MISSION.
JUST KEEP HIM ALIVE LONG ENOUGH
TO DESTROY THE EARTH SHIP.
AFTER THAT, HIS HEALTH
IS OF LITTLE CONSEQUENCE.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I JUST RECEIVED A TRANSMISSION.
OUR SCIENTISTS IDENTIFIED
THE BRAIN-WAVE PATTERN.
AND?
IT'S FROM MY WORLD, BUT IT'S NOT
FROM ANY ANDORIAN YOU'D KNOW.
IT'S AENAR.
THEY'RE A KIND OF SUBSPECIES.
BLIND ICE-DWELLERS.
FOR MOST OF OUR HISTORY,
THEY WERE CONSIDERED A MYTH,
STORIES WE TOLD OUR CHILDREN.
BUT 50 YEARS AGO,
THEY WERE DISCOVERED LIVING
IN THE NORTHERN WASTES.
THEY'RE EXTREMELY SECRETIVE.
I CAN COUNT ON ONE HAND
THE NUMBER OF ANDORIANS
WHO'VE SEEN ONE FACE-TO-FACE.
COULD THEY HAVE BUILT A SHIP
LIKE THE MARAUDER?
I SERIOUSLY DOUBT
THEY HAVE THE CAPACITY.
THERE ARE ONLY
A FEW THOUSAND OF THEM LEFT,
AND EVEN IF THEY COULD,
THEY'RE PACIFISTS.
THEY DON'T BELIEVE IN VIOLENCE.
ONE OF THEM DOES.
SEEMS THAT WAY.
WE NEED TO FIND OUT
WHO'S CONTROLLING THAT SHIP.
AGREED.
-TRAVIS.
-Yes, sir.
SET A COURSE FOR ANDORIA.
MAXIMUM WARP.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU SHOULD REST.
I JUST NEED A SECOND.
PHLOX THINKS IT'S TOO SOON
FOR YOU TO RETURN TO DUTY.
PHLOX?
YOU WERE TALKING
TO HIM ABOUT ME?
IT CAME UP IN CONVERSATION.
RIGHT.
WELL, I DON'T HAVE THE OPTION
OF TAKING A BREAK.
THE CAPTAIN NEEDS
THIS DONE FAST.
I CAN MANAGE.
YOU MIGHT BE THE BEST THERE IS
AT CRUNCHING NUMBERS,
BUT WHEN IT COMES TO ACTUALLY
STICKING THINGS TOGETHER,
YOU'RE A LITTLE
OUT OF YOUR LEAGUE.
THESE WORK BETTER WHEN YOU
STRIP OFF THE DURANITE CAPS.
DON'T ASK ME WHY.
THEY JUST DO.
I'LL MAKE A NOTE OF THAT.
YOU KNOW...
WHEN I WAS ON THAT SHIP
WITH MALCOLM,
I WAS CONVINCED
I WAS GONNA DIE.
YOU EVER BEEN THERE?
SINCE ENTERPRISE WAS LAUNCHED,
WE'VE ALL BEEN NEAR DEATH
ON MORE THAN ONE OCCASION.
I'M NOT TALKING CLOSE SCRAPES.
I MEAN, WHEN YOU'RE
IN A BAD SITUATION,
AND YOU KNOW THIS IS IT.
THERE'S NO WAY OUT,
AND YOU HAVE TIME
TO THINK ABOUT IT.
IN THE EXPANSE, WHEN WE WERE
ATTEMPTING TO DESTROY SPHERE 41,
I DIDN'T BELIEVE WE'D SURVIVE.
WHAT WENT THROUGH YOUR MIND?
WHETHER OR NOT
TO TRANSFER AUXILIARY POWER
TO THE DEFLECTOR ARRAY.
WHY DO YOU ASK?
JUST CURIOUS.
THE AENAR COMPOUND IS SURROUNDED
BY A DAMPENING FIELD.
ONCE YOU'RE INSIDE, YOU WON'T
BE ABLE TO CONTACT THE SHIP.
I'D FEEL
MUCH BETTER ABOUT THIS
IF YOU'D TAKE A COUPLE OF MACOs
WITH YOU.
WE GO IN THERE
WITH A SHOW OF FORCE,
WE WON'T GET A THING
OUT OF THEM.
WE'RE GOING ALONE.
CAPTAIN, WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THESE PEOPLE.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
ENERGIZE.
[ SIGHS ]
TASTE THAT AIR.
[ CHUCKLES ]
REALLY GETS THE BLOOD RUNNING.
28 BELOW?
LUCKY FOR YOU,
IT'S THE MIDDLE OF SUMMER.
YEAH.
THE ENTRANCE
IS 20 METERS AHEAD.
THE VULCANS SAY
THAT THE DESERT
TEACHES MEN
THE MEANING OF ENDURANCE.
BUT IT'S THE ICE
THAT FORGES REAL STRENGTH.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
ANYTHING CAN SURVIVE HERE.
IT ISN'T EASY.
ANDORIAN CITIES
ARE BUILT UNDERGROUND
TO TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF GEOTHERMAL ENERGY.
I DIDN'T SEE THE SUN
TILL I WAS 15.
[ GRUNTS ]
CAREFUL, SHRAN. YOU DON'T
HAVE YOUR BALANCE BACK YET.
HANDS OFF, PINK-SKIN.
[ SIGHS ]
[ BEEPING ]
THESE TUNNELS BRANCH OUT
FOR THOUSANDS OF KILOMETERS.
NOT A GOOD PLACE TO GET LOST.
WE'LL BE READY TO LAUNCH
IN 12 HOURS.
-AND THE PILOT?
-HE'S RESTING.
WILL HE BE READY?
I'LL MAKE SURE THAT HE IS.
SPOKEN LIKE A SOLDIER.
I'M A SCIENTIST.
WE'RE ALL SOLDIERS, NIJIL...
FROM THE MOMENT WE'RE BORN.
WHEN WE FORGET THAT,
WE INVITE DISASTER.
YOU KNOW I WAS ONCE A SENATOR?
NO.
MANY YEARS AGO.
VRAX AND I WERE COLLEAGUES.
I EVEN CONSIDERED
HIM A FRIEND.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I MADE THE MISTAKE
OF CHALLENGING
THE PRECEPT
OF UNLIMITED EXPANSION.
I ASKED THE QUESTION --
IS CONQUEST TRULY
THE BEST COURSE FOR OUR PEOPLE?
AND I WAS EXPELLED.
I'M SORRY.
I'M NOT TRYING
TO EVOKE YOUR PITY.
I WANT YOU TO LEARN
FROM MY EXPERIENCE.
WHEN I WAS LED AWAY
FROM THE SENATE CHAMBER,
I VOWED NEVER TO REPEAT MY ERROR
AND NEVER TO FORGET MY PURPOSE.
I UNDERSTAND.
CONTINUE WITH
YOUR PREPARATIONS.
ICE-BORES. WORMS.
THEY LIVE IN THE ICE.
GENERATE HEAT THROUGH
A CHEMICAL REACTION.
BIG SWARM CAME THROUGH HERE
A DAY OR TWO AGO.
I'M SURE PHLOX WOULD LOVE
TO GET HIS HANDS ON ONE.
BEST TO AVOID THEM.
WHEN I WAS A BOY,
I STUMBLED INTO A LARGE DEN.
WOUND UP WITH THIRD-DEGREE BURNS
OVER HALF MY BODY.
[ GROANS ]
SHRAN, LISTEN TO ME.
WE SHOULD FIND ANOTHER WAY.
AFRAID OF HEIGHTS, CAPTAIN?
SHRAN!
[ GRUNTING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
THE ICE GAVE OUT BENEATH ME.
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROANING ]
YOU'RE LOSING A LOT OF BLOOD.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GROANING ]
HOLD STILL.
BLEEDING'S STOPPED.
BUT IF YOU MOVE,
IT COULD START AGAIN.
WE CAN'T STAY HERE.
WE'LL FREEZE TO DEATH.
ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
WE'RE WELL INSIDE
THE DAMPENING FIELD.
IT DOESN'T HURT TO TRY.
HOW FAR ARE WE FROM THE AENAR?
I THINK WE JUST
GOT A LOT CLOSER.
HELLO.
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
MY FRIEND'S BEEN HURT.
WE'LL ASSIST YOU.
THERE'S NOT AS MUCH DATA ON THE
NEURAL INTERFACE AS I'D LIKE.
IT'S ALL WE HAVE.
I CAN CONNECT SOMEONE TO THE
UNIT, BUT IT WILL BE DANGEROUS.
HOW DANGEROUS?
WELL, IF THE INTERFACE
MALFUNCTIONS,
THERE COULD BE
SEVERE NEUROLYTIC SHOCK,
POSSIBLY RESULTING
IN BRAIN DAMAGE.
THERE'S GOT TO BE SOME WAY
WE CAN MAKE IT SAFER.
DIAGNOSTICS WILL ONLY TELL US
SO MUCH, I'M AFRAID.
WHEN CAN WE TEST IT?
A DAY.
I WANT TO BE THE FIRST ONE
TO TRY IT OUT.
YOU'RE NOT TELEPATHIC.
IT WOULDN'T BE A TRUE MEASURE
OF THE UNIT'S EFFECTIVENESS.
WELL, AT LEAST WE'LL FIND OUT
IF IT CAUSES BRAIN DAMAGE.
I'LL TEST THE UNIT.
YOU'RE THE RANKING OFFICER.
TOO RISKY.
CONSIDERING WHAT'S AT STAKE,
THE RISK IS ACCEPTABLE.
WE COULD AT LEAST WAIT
UNTIL THE CAPTAIN GETS BACK.
OUR GOAL SHOULD BE
TO HAVE THE UNIT READY
BY THE TIME HE RETURNS.
THAT MEANS CONDUCTING
A FULL SERIES OF TESTS.
THE DISCUSSION'S CLOSED.
WE HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO DO.
YOUR WOUND IS HEALING WELL.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO WALK
ON YOUR OWN IN A FEW HOURS.
MY THANKS.
YOU'RE CAPTAIN ARCHER.
YOU CAN READ MINDS.
WE HAVE A STRICT LAW HERE,
CAPTAIN.
NO ONE MAY ENTER ANOTHER'S
THOUGHTS WITHOUT PERMISSION.
I KNOW YOUR NAME
BECAUSE THE ANDORIAN CHANCELLOR
CONTACTED US.
I NEED TO SPEAK
WITH SOMEONE IN AUTHORITY.
WE ASSIGN OUR LEADERS
AS THE NEED ARISES.
FOR THIS OCCASION,
I HAVE BEEN CHOSEN AS SPEAKER.
I TAKE IT YOU KNOW
WHY WE'RE HERE.
I KNOW WHAT THE ANDORIANS
HAVE TOLD US.
SOMEONE'S BEEN
ATTACKING YOUR SHIPS.
AND YOU BELIEVE WE'RE INVOLVED.
IT'S A BIT MORE COMPLICATED
THAN THAT.
IT WILL SAVE TIME
AND FOSTER OUR TRUST
IF I CAN HAVE YOUR THOUGHTS.
GO AHEAD.
YOU HAVE
AN INTERESTING MIND, CAPTAIN.
MANY FACETS.
THANK YOU.
SOME OF THOSE FACETS
ARE IN CONFLICT.
-THAT EXPLAINS A LOT.
-SHRAN.
THE EVIDENCE YOU'VE GATHERED
APPEARS IRREFUTABLE.
IT SEEMS THERE WAS AN AENAR
CONTROLLING THAT SHIP.
BUT YOU'RE SKEPTICAL.
W-WE'RE A NONVIOLENT PEOPLE.
THAT A MEMBER OF OUR RACE
COULD CAUSE SO MUCH DEATH,
IT'S EXTREMELY DISTURBING.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO IT COULD BE?
THERE'S ONE POSSIBILITY.
WHO?
A YEAR AGO,
ONE OF OUR CITIZENS DISAPPEARED
WHILE COLLECTING ICE-BORES.
WE ASSUMED HE'D BEEN KILLED
IN AN ACCIDENT,
BUT WE NEVER FOUND HIS BODY.
NOW YOU KNOW WHY.
GAREB WOULD NOT BE DOING THIS
VOLUNTARILY.
YOU THINK HE WAS ABDUCTED?
IT'S THE BEST EXPLANATION.
IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHY HE'S DOING IT.
HE HAS TO BE STOPPED.
THIS DEVICE YOU'RE BUILDING
ABOARD YOUR SHIP?
WE'RE HOPING
IT WILL DISRUPT THE SIGNAL
THAT'S CONTROLLING
THE MARAUDER.
YOU WILL NEED ONE OF US
TO OPERATE IT.
YOU OWE US
THAT MUCH, AT LEAST.
I'LL CONSULT WITH THE OTHERS.
COFFEE. STRONG.
-COMMANDER.
-HEY.
TRIP.
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN
FOR MY SAFETY.
I JUST DON'T WANT ENTERPRISE
TO LOSE A GOOD OFFICER.
I THINK YOU'RE LETTING YOUR
FEELINGS IMPACT YOUR WORK.
MY WORK'S AS GOOD
AS IT'S EVER BEEN.
AS FAR AS MY FEELINGS GO...
THEY'RE PURELY PROFESSIONAL.
I'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE TO SLEEP
WITH SOMEONE STANDING
AT THE FOOT OF MY BED.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO DISTURB YOU.
ACTUALLY, I WAS AWAKE.
WHAT IS IT?
I'VE NEVER MET A BLUE-SKIN.
YOU'RE BLIND.
HOW CAN YOU TELL
MY SKIN IS BLUE?
DON'T ASK ME TO EXPLAIN.
I WAS NEVER VERY GOOD
AT SCIENCE.
NEITHER WAS I.
IS IT TRUE
THAT WHERE YOU COME FROM,
THE TEMPERATURE RISES ABOVE
FREEZING FOR WEEKS AT A TIME?
EVERY FEW YEARS,
THERE'S A HEAT WAVE.
I'VE BEEN ON WORLDS
WHERE THE TEMPERATURE
IS ONLY SLIGHTLY BELOW
THE BOILING POINT OF WATER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE SUCH A PLACE.
I'M TRYING TO FORGET IT.
I LOST 10% OF MY BODY WEIGHT
IN TWO DAYS.
[ LAUGHS ]
I CAME HERE TO APOLOGIZE.
FOR WHAT?
WHEN I SAW YOU
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
I SENSED SOME OF YOUR THOUGHTS.
I-I DIDN'T INTEND TO.
IT'S NEVER BEEN ALL THAT HARD
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT I'M THINKING.
I KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO LOSE SOMEONE.
GAREB, THE ONE WHO'S MISSING...
HE'S MY BROTHER.
I'M SORRY.
HE WOULD NEVER HURT ANYONE,
NOT INTENTIONALLY.
SO WE'VE BEEN TOLD.
DO YOU THINK HE'S IN PAIN?
THERE'S NO WAY OF KNOWING.
I HAVE NIGHTMARES.
GAREB'S BOUND,
LOCKED IN A STRANGE CAGE.
HE'S CALLING FOR ME.
HE WANTS ME TO RESCUE HIM.
FORGIVE ME.
[ GASPS ]
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
I JUST NEED A MOMENT.
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY.
INDICATOR'S MOVIN'. DOC?
SO FAR, SO GOOD.
I'LL BE DAMNED.
IT'S WORKING.
[ BEEPING ]
[ GASPS ]
SHE OKAY?
HER SYNAPTIC RESPONSE
IS ERRATIC.
I'LL BE FINE.
[ BEEPING CONTINUES ]
[ MOANS ]
-[ BEEPING ]
-IT'S GETTING WORSE, COMMANDER.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
SHUT IT DOWN!
[ MACHINES SHUT OFF ]
HMM.
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
IT WORKED.
I'LL REST FOR A FEW MINUTES,
AND THEN WE'LL TRY AGAIN.
YOU SAID GAREB WAS ABDUCTED.
IF THAT'S TRUE,
DON'T YOU WANT TO HELP HIM?
NOT WITH VIOLENCE.
WE'RE TRYING
TO STOP VIOLENCE.
I WON'T DENY THAT
YOUR INTENTIONS ARE HONORABLE.
BUT OUR DECISION STANDS.
FORGET IT, CAPTAIN.
THEY'VE NEVER EVEN HELPED
DEFEND THEIR OWN WORLD.
WE'RE WASTING OUR TIME.
SYSTEMS READY.
LAUNCH THE DRONES.
[ PULSING ]
YOU NEED TO REST.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH REST.
WE SHOULD CLEAR
THE DAMPENING FIELD SOON.
WAIT!
WHAT IS IT?
A SWARM.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
IT'LL TAKE A FEW MINUTES
FOR THEM TO PASS.
GAREB AND I LOVED
CHASING ICE-BORES.
ONCE, WE FOLLOWED A SWARM
FOR TWO HOURS,
CAUGHT HUNDREDS OF THEM.
WE WERE ALMOST AT THE SURFACE.
MY FAMILY WAS VERY WORRIED.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE
WORRIED ABOUT ME NOW.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
I WON'T ABANDON MY BROTHER.
WHAT'S IT LIKE, YOUR SHIP?
WARM.
SHE WANTS TO TRY AGAIN.
YOU THINK IT'S SMART?
YOU KNOW THE RISKS.
SO DOES COMMANDER T'POL.
COMMANDER...
SHE'S DOING HER JOB.
SHE'S GONNA HURT HERSELF.
TAKE MY ADVICE --
DON'T INTERFERE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M GETTING THIS
FROM YOU NOW.
HAS EVERYONE ON THIS SHIP
GONE CRAZY?
NOT EVERYONE.
-OH, I'M CRAZY?
-IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
AS FAR AS I KNOW, THERE ARE
NO SPECIES IN THE GALAXY
THAT HAVE MASTERED THE ART
OF MIXING ROMANCE AND VOCATION.
YOU'RE THE LAST ONE THAT SHOULD
BE GIVING ME A LECTURE.
VULCAN NEUROPRESSURE
WAS YOUR IDEA.
YOU WERE HAVING
TROUBLE SLEEPING.
WHAT THE HELL AM I GONNA DO?
THIS IS THE ONE AILMENT THAT IS
UNIVERSALLY UNTREATABLE.
YOU'LL HAVE TO SUFFER
THROUGH IT.
WE'VE BEEN HERE BEFORE.
HE'S RIGHT.
WE'RE GOING IN CIRCLES.
THEY'RE TRYING TO STOP US.
HOW?
THEY'RE NOT LETTING US SEE
THE PATH TO THE SURFACE.
HOW COULD THAT BE POSSIBLE?
IT'S TIME TO COME BACK.
I CAN'T.
THEY'RE FIGHTING A WAR.
DO YOU WANT TO BE
A PART OF THAT?
I DON'T WANT TO FIGHT ANYONE.
I WANT TO HELP MY BROTHER.
HELP HIM BY STANDING UP
FOR WHAT WE BELIEVE IN.
SHE'S DOING WHAT
SHE THINKS IS RIGHT.
-SHE'S BETRAYING HER PEOPLE.
-THAT'S NOT TRUE.
SHOULDN'T SHE BE ALLOWED
TO FOLLOW HER OWN CONSCIENCE?
SHE'S NOT FOLLOWING
HER CONSCIENCE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
HAVE YOU READ HER MIND?
I THOUGHT THAT WAS
AGAINST YOUR CUSTOM.
JHAMEL.
TAKE MY THOUGHTS.
YOU'RE CERTAIN
THIS IS WHAT YOU WANT?
YES.
VERY WELL.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE RETURNED TO ENTERPRISE,
WHERE WE RECEIVED WORD
THAT THE CARGO SHIP
TICONDEROGA IS MISSING.
ANYTHING ON
LONG-RANGE SENSORS?
-NOT YET.
-WHAT'S OUR E.T.A.?
WE'LL BE AT THEIR LAST KNOWN
COORDINATES IN SIX HOURS.
TELL MALCOLM TO FINISH
HIS UPGRADES TO THE
TARGETING SCANNERS.
IF WE RUN INTO
THAT MARAUDER AGAIN,
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
EVERY SHOT COUNTS.
UNDERSTOOD.
REPORT?
SHE'S GOOD TO GO.
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY.
I'M READY, CAPTAIN.
A LOT OF MOVEMENT.
50% SPIKE.
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
WE CAN STOP
ANY TIME YOU LIKE.
IT'S STRANGELY ENJOYABLE.
SHE'S MAXED IT OUT.
IS THAT GOOD?
VERY GOOD.
IS THERE ANOTHER TEST
WE CAN TRY?
WE COULD SIMULATE
A COURSE CORRECTION.
[ GASPS ]
SYNAPTIC TROUBLE.
[ BEEPING ]
SHUT IT DOWN!
[ SHUDDERING ]
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'VE ARRIVED AT THE LAST KNOWN
COORDINATES OF THE TICONDEROGA.
I'M PICKING UP DEBRIS.
HULL FRAGMENTS.
NACELLE CASINGS.
SEVERAL BODIES, HUMAN.
KEEP SCANNING.
TRY TO FIND THE MARAUDER'S
WARP SIGNATURE.
IS THERE ANY WORD
FROM SICKBAY?
SHE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
BUT PHLOX SAYS IT'S
TOO DANGEROUS TO TRY AGAIN.
LOOKS LIKE WE WENT ALL THE WAY
TO ANDORIA...
FOR NOTHING.
[ SIGHS ]
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU HAD A CONVULSION.
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT NOW.
I WAS DREAMING...
ABOUT GAREB.
I FAILED, DIDN'T I?
RIDICULOUS.
THAT KIND OF BRAVERY
IS NEVER A FAILURE.
I'M A COMMANDER
IN THE IMPERIAL GUARD.
I'D BE AFRAID TO GO
ANYWHERE NEAR THAT THING.
TALAS WAS A FORTUNATE WOMAN.
I WAS THE FORTUNATE ONE.
MY BROTHER'S GOING TO DIE,
ISN'T HE?
I WON'T HEAR THAT FROM YOU.
IT'S HARD TO BE STRONG.
YOU MAKE IT LOOK EASY.
KEEP BEING STRONG.
FOR ME.
A SHIP'S
DROPPING OUT OF WARP.
IT APPEARS TO BE
A TELLARITE FREIGHTER.
TACTICAL ALERT.
HAIL THEM.
TARGET THEIR ENGINES.
IF IT IS A FREIGHTER...
ANYTHING?
100 KILOMETERS.
FIRE.
AIM FOR THEIR WEAPONS!
THEY'RE TOO DAMN FAST.
I CAN'T GET A TARGET LOCK.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
I'M GOING TO THE BRIDGE.
WAIT.
I CAN FEEL HIM.
[ LASER FIRE ]
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
TAKE ME TO THE DEVICE.
I NEED TO TRY AGAIN.
I CAN'T ALLOW IT.
YOU BARELY SURVIVED
THE LAST ATTEMPTS.
I CAN REACH HIM.
I CAN MAKE HIM STOP.
LET HER TRY.
ENTERPRISE IS
TAKING HEAVY DAMAGE.
TARGET WITH THE SECOND DRONE.
ATTACK VECTOR 177.
IT MAY NOT BE NECESSARY.
FOLLOW MY ORDERS.
YES, ADMIRAL.
[ BEEPING ]
ANOTHER SHIP'S APPROACHING,
BEARING 016 MARK 12.
AN ANDORIAN BATTLE CRUISER.
T'POL?
ITS POWER SIGNATURE
IS NOT ANDORIAN.
TARGET THEM!
CAPTAIN, I'M PICKING UP
AN ENERGY READING FROM SICKBAY.
IT'S THE TELEPRESENCE UNIT.
ARCHER TO SICKBAY.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
JHAMEL'S GOING TO
MAKE ANOTHER ATTEMPT.
IS SHE UP TO IT?
SHE'S QUITE INSISTENT.
[ BEEPING ]
CORTICAL FLUCTUATION.
IT COULD TRIGGER A SEIZURE.
JHAMEL.
I CAN DO IT.
DISCONNECT HER. NOW!
-NO!
-SHE CAN DO THIS.
THEY'VE LOST WARP POWER.
CONTINUE TARGETING
THEIR ENGINES.
SOMEONE'S TAPPING INTO
THE TELEMETRIC ARRAY.
[ Thinking ]
JHAMEL?
IT'S ME.
IT'S NOT POSSIBLE. HOW?
YOU HAVE TO STOP
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
WHERE ARE YOU?
I'M ON THE SHIP
YOU'RE ATTACKING.
BOTH DRONES
ARE COMING TO A STOP.
WE'RE DEFENSELESS.
THEY'VE STOPPED FIRING.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE DEAD.
THEY SAID I WAS
THE LAST SURVIVING AENAR.
THEY LIED TO YOU.
I'VE KILLED SO MANY PEOPLE.
IT WASN'T YOU.
IT WAS THEM.
THEY FORCED YOU.
YOU CAN STOP IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO.
THE FIRST DRONE
IS TARGETING THE SECOND!
TAKE ALL WEAPONS OFFLINE.
I'VE LOST ACCESS.
-THEY'RE ATTACKING EACH OTHER.
-LET'S GIVE THEM A HAND.
PHOTONIC TORPEDOES --
FULL SPREAD.
AYE, SIR.
STOP THIS. NOW.
NO!
RESUME YOUR ATTACK
ON THE EARTH SHIP.
REMEMBER ME, JHAMEL.
GAREB!
[ BOTH GASP ]
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
THERE'S BEEN NO SIGN
OF ANY OTHER MARAUDER SHIPS.
WE'RE RETURNING SHRAN
AND JHAMEL TO ANDORIA.
I WANT TO THANK YOU AGAIN.
I OWE YOU THANKS.
IF I HADN'T COME WITH YOU, MY
BROTHER WOULD HAVE DIED ALONE.
GOODBYE, CAPTAIN.
GOODBYE.
I REGRET...
MUCH OF WHAT HAPPENED
BETWEEN US RECENTLY.
SAME HERE.
WHEN YOU LOSE YOUR SHIP,
YOU AREN'T USUALLY REWARDED
WITH ANOTHER ONE.
I MAY NOT SEE YOU
FOR A WHILE.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING WE CAN DO
OR SAY ON YOUR BEHALF...
I APPRECIATE THE OFFER.
LET'S JUST SEE
WHAT THE FUTURE BRINGS.
TRY TO STAY OUT OF TROUBLE,
PINK-SKIN.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING OVER
YOUR REPORT.
I THINK YOU'RE BEING
A LITTLE HARD ON YOURSELF.
THERE'S NO GETTING AROUND IT.
I MISSED A 10-DEGREE VARIANCE
IN THE TELEPRESENCE EMITTER.
I SPOKE TO PHLOX.
HE DOESN'T THINK IT HAD ANYTHING
TO DO WITH JHAMEL'S SEIZURE.
BUT HE CAN'T BE SURE.
EITHER WAY,
I SHOULD HAVE CAUGHT IT.
WE WERE ALL UNDER
A LOT OF PRESSURE.
MY MIND WASN'T ON THE JOB.
IF THAT WERE TRUE,
YOU PROBABLY WOULDN'T
BE STANDIN' HERE NOW.
CAPTAIN, I WANT A TRANSFER.
WHERE?
COLUMBIA.
THEY NEED EXPERIENCED PEOPLE.
YOU'VE TURNED THEM DOWN
TWICE BEFORE.
WHY NOW?
I THINK I CAN DO SOME GOOD
OVER THERE.
I NEED YOU HERE, TRIP.
THEY NEED ME MORE.
WHAT'S THIS REALLY ABOUT?
I TOLD YOU.
I HAVEN'T HEARD ONE THING
THAT EXPLAINS THIS.
I'VE SAID EVERYTHING
I WANT TO.
THAT'S IT?
I'M SUPPOSED TO ACCEPT THAT?
AND IF I REFUSE YOUR TRANSFER?
CAPTAIN...
AS A FRIEND, I'M ASKING YOU.
LET ME DO THIS.
IT'S YOUR CAREER, TRIP.
BUT AS A FRIEND...
I'M ASKING YOU TO STAY.
I CAN'T.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
DISMISSED.