[ GROWLING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
NOVEMBER 27, 2154.
WE'VE RETURNED HOME
FOR THE OFFICIAL LAUNCH
OF OUR SISTER SHIP, COLUMBIA.
ON A PERSONAL NOTE,
I'LL ALSO BE SAYING GOODBYE TO
ONE HELL OF A CHIEF ENGINEER.
-[ DOOR CHIMES ]
-YEAH?
SHE'S A THING OF BEAUTY.
COLUMBIA'S VIRTUALLY IDENTICAL
TO ENTERPRISE.
WELL, A GOOD ENGINEER
CAN SEE THE DIFFERENCES.
YOU COMING TO
THE MESS HALL LATER?
MY GOING-AWAY PARTY?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THE LOGIC
BEHIND THIS TRANSFER.
YOU'RE NOT BEING PROMOTED.
YOU THINK I'M DOING THIS
TO ADVANCE MY CAREER?
YOU WOULDN'T LEAVE
CAPTAIN ARCHER WITHOUT
SUFFICIENT REASON.
WELL, FOR ONE THING,
THIS IS A NEW CHALLENGE.
IT TOOK ME A YEAR TO
FINE-TUNE ENTERPRISE.
I FIGURE I CAN DO THE SAME
FOR CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ
IN HALF THE TIME.
SHE NEEDS A CHIEF ENGINEER
WHO'S BEEN OUT THERE,
HAS THE EXPERIENCE.
ARE YOU LEAVING
BECAUSE OF ME?
LOOK, STARFLEET'S
APPROVED THE TRANSFER.
YOU DIDN'T ANSWER MY QUESTION.
[ SIGHS ]
THIS MAY COME AS A SHOCK,
BUT NOT EVERYTHING IN MY LIFE
REVOLVES AROUND YOU.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
I'M GLAD WE GOT HERE EARLY.
HMM. THERE NEVER USED
TO BE A WAIT TO GET IN.
YOU DIDN'T THINK
MADAME CHANG'S
WAS GONNA BE YOUR LITTLE SECRET
FOREVER, DID YOU?
THERE ARE A LOT OF
STARFLEET PEOPLE HERE.
THAT'S PROBABLY MY FAULT.
I TOLD A FEW FRIENDS
ABOUT THE PLACE.
-A FEW?
-I'M A COM OFFICER.
IF THERE'S ONE THING
I KNOW HOW TO DO,
-IT'S DISSEMINATE
INFORMATION.
-[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME HOW YOUR
MEETING WENT TODAY AT THE I.M.E.
THEY ASKED IF I WAS INTERESTED
IN BECOMING
DIRECTOR OF XENOBIOLOGY.
THAT'S GREAT.
ARE YOU GONNA ACCEPT?
I'M CONSIDERING IT.
THE TRUTH IS, I'VE GROWN
RATHER FOND OF MY SHIPMATES.
I'M NOT CERTAIN I'M READY
TO LEAVE THEM JUST YET.
WHAT WOULD YOU SUGGEST?
I'M THE WRONG PERSON TO ASK.
I'VE GOT A VESTED INTEREST
IN KEEPING YOU AROUND.
YOU, DENOBULAN.
COME WITH US.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
MAYBE YOU DIDN'T HEAR ME.
[ GRUNTING ]
OH!
[ SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HOSHI.
-I'M ALL RIGHT, SIR.
-WHO DID THIS?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TRYING TO DETERMINE.
COMMANDER COLLINS,
STARFLEET SECURITY.
JONATHAN ARCHER.
THIS IS LIEUTENANT REED.
THERE WERE THREE MEN.
THEY WERE IN THE SHADOWS.
I-I DIDN'T GET
A GOOD LOOK AT THEM.
YOU TOLD ME BEFORE
THAT ONE OF THEM
SAID SOMETHING TO THE OTHERS?
RIGHT BEFORE I PASSED OUT.
I'M PRETTY SURE
IT WASN'T ENGLISH.
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT HE SAID?
I'M SORRY, SIR.
THE ONLY DNA WE'VE RECOVERED
BELONGS TO ENSIGN SATO
AND TO YOUR DOCTOR.
WE DID FIND SOME RESIDUAL
IONIZATION TRACES HERE.
A TRANSPORTER SIGNATURE?
VERY FEW PEOPLE HAVE ACCESS
TO THAT KIND OF TECHNOLOGY.
STILL,
IT'S A LIKELY EXPLANATION.
DR. PHLOX WAS INVOLVED
IN AN ALTERCATION
THE LAST TIME
HE WAS IN SAN FRANCISCO.
YOU THINK THIS IS RELATED?
ASSAULTS AGAINST ALIENS
ARE STILL PRETTY RARE.
IF THE MAN WHO ATTACKED HIM
WAS HOLDING A GRUDGE --
HE WAS A LOUDMOUTH IN A BAR.
I DOUBT HE COULD FIND HIS HEAD
WITH BOTH HANDS,
NEVER MIND ORGANIZE
A KIDNAPPING.
WE'RE PURSUING ALL AVENUES.
EXCUSE ME,
CAPTAIN, LIEUTENANT.
CHECK WITH
STARFLEET OPERATIONS.
SEE IF THEIR SATELLITES
PICKED UP
ANY TRANSPORTER ACTIVITY
THIS EVENING.
THE DILITHIUM MATRIX HAS GOT TO
BE ALIGNED WITHIN .3 MICRONS.
THE SPECS SAY .5.
WHO DO YOU THINK
WROTE THOSE SPECS?
-A WARP-FIELD SPECIALIST?
-EXACTLY.
SOME GUY WHO'S PROBABLY NEVER
BEEN OUTSIDE THE SOLAR SYSTEM.
I'VE SPENT THE LAST 3 1/2 YEARS
CRAWLING INSIDE
ONE OF THESE ENGINES.
I KNOW WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
AYE, SIR.
BIGGS, PIERCE.
I WANT YOU TO RECALIBRATE
THE FIELD STABILIZERS.
RIVERS AND STRONG,
START WITH
THE INJECTOR ASSEMBLY.
THIS BUCKET OF BOLTS
WAS SUPPOSED TO LEAVE DRY DOCK
SIX MONTHS AGO.
I GUARANTEE YOU,
COLUMBIA'S GONNA
WARP OUT OF ORBIT
BEFORE THE END OF THE WEEK.
LET'S GET TO WORK.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
IT'S CUSTOMARY TO REPORT TO
THE CAPTAIN AFTER A TRANSFER.
I'M SORRY, MA'AM.
I WANTED TO SEE WHAT
THE SITUATION WAS LIKE
BEFORE WE SPOKE.
COMMANDER CHARLES TUCKER,
REPORTING FOR DUTY.
WELCOME ABOARD.
-TRIP, IS IT?
-THAT'S RIGHT.
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
CAN SHE BE SALVAGED?
I THINK
THERE'S A GOOD CHANCE.
ANY NEWS ON DR. PHLOX?
NOT SO FAR. IF I HEAR ANYTHING,
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
YOU CERTAINLY KNOW
HOW TO MOTIVATE THE TROOPS.
WE'LL BE PULLING TRIPLE SHIFTS
IF WE WANT TO MEET
THIS NEW LAUNCH DATE.
YOU STILL NEED TO EAT.
CAPTAIN'S MESS, TOMORROW,
1800 HOURS?
WE CAN TRADE STORIES
ABOUT YOUR FORMER C.O.
I'LL BE THERE.
COMMANDER,
DROP BY THE QUARTERMASTER'S
AT THE END OF YOUR SHIFT.
MA'AM?
MIGHT WANT TO...
UPDATE YOUR UNIFORM.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
WE'VE HEARD NOTHING
FROM THE KIDNAPPERS,
NOT EVEN A RANSOM DEMAND.
I'VE SPOKEN WITH
THE DENOBULAN AMBASSADOR.
HE'S NOTIFIED
THE DOCTOR'S WIVES.
HOSHI THOUGHT SHE OVERHEARD
ONE OF THE KIDNAPPERS
SAY SOMETHING
IN ANOTHER LANGUAGE,
BUT SHE WAS
SEMI-CONSCIOUS AT THE TIME.
MAYBE YOU COULD
HELP HER REMEMBER.
A MIND MELD?
I'VE NEVER INITIATED
A MELD BEFORE.
I DON'T HAVE
THE PROPER TRAINING.
I KNOW IT'S DANGEROUS.
-BUT I CAN WALK
YOU THROUGH IT.
-YOU?
I HAD SURAK'S KATRA
IN MY HEAD FOR FOUR DAYS.
I PICKED UP A FEW TRICKS.
COMPUTER,
ACCESS SATELLITE LOGS 137.
TIME PARAMETERS
1900 AND 1945, TODAY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
WHAT?
STARFLEET OPERATIONS,
THIS IS LIEUTENANT MALCOLM REED
ABOARD ENTERPRISE.
PLEASE ACKNOWLEDGE.
BURNING THE MIDNIGHT OIL,
LIEUTENANT?
SIR?
I THOUGHT I WAS CALLING
STARFLEET OPS.
LET ME GUESS.
YOU WANT TO KNOW WHY THE GRID
COVERING SAN FRANCISCO
WAS DOWN FOR MAINTENANCE
TONIGHT.
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
MEET ME AT THIS ADDRESS
IN ONE HOUR.
MY MIND TO YOUR MIND.
OUR MINDS ARE MERGING.
OUR MINDS ARE ONE.
NOTHING'S HAPPENING.
T'POL, TRY TO RELAX
YOUR EMOTIONAL SUPPRESSION
JUST A LITTLE.
I FEEL WHAT YOU FEEL.
I KNOW WHAT YOU KNOW.
[ GASPS ]
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
YES, PERFECTLY.
YOU AND THE DOCTOR HAVE
JUST LEFT THE RESTAURANT.
-I'M GLAD WE GOT HERE EARLY.
-HMM.
THERE NEVER USED
TO BE A WAIT TO GET IN.
GOOD.
THEY ASKED
IF I WAS INTERESTED
IN BECOMING
DIRECTOR OF XENOBIOLOGY.
-WHERE WERE YOU ATTACKED?
-THERE.
THE TRUTH IS, I'VE GROWN
RATHER FOND OF MY SHIPMATES.
-I'M NOT CERTAIN I'M READY
TO LEAVE THEM JUST YET.
-DO YOU SEE THEM?
WHAT WOULD YOU SUGGEST?
YES.
YOU, DENOBULAN.
COME WITH US.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
MAYBE YOU DIDN'T HEAR ME.
[ GRUNTING ]
FOCUS ON THE MOMENT.
PUT ASIDE ANY PAIN.
OH!
[ SPEAKS RIGELIAN ]
[ BOTH SPEAK RIGELIAN ]
"BRING HIM WITH US."
IT'S RIGELIAN.
A RIGELIAN FREIGHTER
LEFT ORBIT
TWO HOURS
AFTER PHLOX'S ABDUCTION.
ACCORDING TO THEIR FLIGHT PLAN,
THEY WERE HEADED
FOR PROXIMA COLONY.
THIS TRAJECTORY WON'T TAKE THEM
ANYWHERE NEAR PROXIMA COLONY.
-ENSIGN.
-SIR?
PUT ADMIRAL GARDNER THROUGH
TO MY READY ROOM.
SHORE LEAVES ARE CANCELED.
GET EVERYONE BACK ONBOARD.
AM I TO UNDERSTAND
YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR TAKING
THAT SATELLITE GRID OFFLINE?
NOT ME PERSONALLY.
BUT YOU'RE INVOLVED.
[ SCOFFS ]
PHLOX IS MY FRIEND.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE HE IS?
WE HAVE AN ASSIGNMENT
FOR YOU.
I WASN'T AWARE THAT I WAS
STILL A PART OF YOUR SECTION.
THERE'S A JOB
THAT NEEDS DOING, LIEUTENANT,
AND IT MAY BE THE ONLY WAY
TO SAVE YOUR FRIEND'S LIFE.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
WELCOME TO QU'VAT COLONY,
DOCTOR.
YOU WILL WORK WITH DR. ANTAAK.
I WILL DO NOTHING OF THE KIND.
THEN YOU WILL DIE.
I'M CERTAIN THERE
ARE EASIER WAYS
FOR YOU TO RECRUIT
A NEW LAB ASSISTANT.
YOU MISUNDERSTAND ME, DOCTOR.
ANTAAK WILL BE ASSISTING YOU.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
DOCTOR.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
I WOULDN'T EXPECT
YOU TO REMEMBER,
BUT WE MET BRIEFLY
FIVE YEARS AGO,
AT THE I.M.E. CONFERENCE
ON TIBURON.
I DON'T RECALL MEETING
A KLINGON AT THAT CONFERENCE.
I WAS DISGUISED AS A MEMBER
OF THE MAZARITE DELEGATION.
MY PEOPLE WEREN'T INVITED.
I WILL LET YOU TWO
GET REACQUAINTED.
I SUGGEST YOU WORK QUICKLY,
DOCTOR.
I EXPECT A PROGRESS REPORT
BY SUNRISE.
YOU MUST FORGIVE
THE GENERAL'S CONDUCT.
THE WARRIOR CASTE HAS LITTLE USE
FOR SOCIAL PROTOCOLS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT WITH ME?
THE EMPIRE IS FACING
ITS GRAVEST THREAT
SINCE THE HUR'Q INVASION.
A VIRUS IS SPREADING
FROM PLANET TO PLANET.
MILLIONS ARE ALREADY INFECTED.
IF THIS CONTINUES,
THE KLINGON SPECIES
WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
WHY DIDN'T YOU SIMPLY
ASK FOR OUR HELP?
STARFLEET AND DENOBULA
WOULD HAVE PROVIDED YOU
WITH ALL OF THE SPECIALISTS
YOU'D NEED.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE KLINGON WAY, DOCTOR.
TO ASK FOR ASSISTANCE
WOULD MAKE US LOOK WEAK
IN THE EYES OF OUR ENEMIES.
IT COULD EVEN INCITE REBELLION.
WHY ME?
I WAS IMPRESSED BY YOUR LECTURE
AT THE CONFERENCE.
YOUR PAPER ON VIRAL PROPAGATION
WAS VERY INSIGHTFUL.
WHAT FIELD OF STUDY
ARE YOU IN, PRECISELY?
METAGENIC RESEARCH.
I'VE ALREADY
ISOLATED THE VIRUS.
I ASSUME YOU'LL WANT TO START
BY MAPPING THE NUCLEOTIDES?
IT WASN'T MY IDEA
TO ABDUCT YOU.
NEVERTHELESS, YOU ARE HERE.
MILLIONS OF LIVES ARE AT RISK.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THE FREIGHTER'S WARP TRAIL
HAS TERMINATED.
THEY MAY HAVE DROPPED
TO IMPULSE.
HOW LONG TO INTERCEPT?
AT OUR CURRENT SPEED, 8.2 HOURS.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
-COMMANDER KELBY, RESPOND.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
KELBY HERE, SIR.
We could use
a little more speed.
THE INJECTORS
ARE RUNNING AT 105%.
COMMANDER TUCKER'S PUSHED THEM
HIGHER THAN THAT BEFORE.
I'll see what
I can do, Captain.
I DON'T KNOW WHO'S
IN CHARGE OF YOUR MESS HALL,
BUT HE COULD GIVE THE CHEF ON
ENTERPRISE A RUN FOR HIS MONEY.
I STOLE HIM FROM THE REPUBLIC.
CAPTAIN JENNINGS SAID
I COULD HAVE ANYTHING
I WANTED WHEN I LEFT,
SO I TOOK HIS COOK.
[ LAUGHS ]
I'VE GOTTEN
TWO TRANSFER REQUESTS
-FROM CREWMEN IN
YOUR DEPARTMENT.
-WHO?
IT'S PROBABLY BETTER
IF I DIDN'T MENTION NAMES.
I DENIED THEM.
YOU'RE ALREADY SHORTHANDED.
QUITE AN IMPRESSION YOU'VE MADE,
COMMANDER.
YOU'VE BEEN ABOARD
LESS THAN TWO DAYS,
AND ALREADY SOME OF YOUR TEAM
WANT TO JUMP SHIP.
I'VE KNOCKED
A FEW HEADS TOGETHER,
BUT WE'RE GETTING THE JOB DONE.
WE'LL BE READY
FOR WARP TRIALS BY THURSDAY.
I WAS SURPRISED
YOU ACCEPTED THIS TRANSFER.
I SAW AN INTERVIEW WITH YOU
AFTER THE XINDI MISSION.
YOU SAID YOU COULDN'T
SEE YOURSELF SERVING
ON ANY OTHER STARSHIP.
WELL, YOU'VE GOT
A GOOD MEMORY, CAPTAIN.
IT COMES IN HANDY.
I WAS GETTING A LITTLE TOO
COMFORTABLE ON ENTERPRISE.
GOT A LOT OF FRIENDS
OVER THERE, BUT...
SOMETIMES IT'S EASIER
TO WORK WITH PEOPLE
WHO ARE JUST COLLEAGUES.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
I WAS ABOUT TO ASK YOU
THE SAME THING.
IS THIS A DAYDREAM?
I'M MEDITATING.
THIS IS WHERE I GO IN MY MIND.
WELL, I WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
YOU'D PICK
A MORE INTERESTING PLACE...
LIKE THE BEACH,
OR ONE OF THOSE FIRE PLAINS
YOU SHOWED ME.
PLEASE LEAVE.
EXACTLY WHERE AM
I SUPPOSED TO GO?
AWAY.
THIS IS MY DAYDREAM.
YOU GO AWAY.
EXCUSE ME, COMMANDER.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, I'M FINE.
THE DIAGNOSTIC YOU ASKED FOR.
THANKS.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Bridge to T'Pol. We're
approaching the coordinates.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
ON MY WAY.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-NO BIO-SIGNS.
I'M READING
SEVERAL BODIES ABOARD.
IS ONE OF THEM DENOBULAN?
THEY'RE ALL RIGELIAN.
[ SIGHS ]
CAN YOU TELL WHO DID THIS?
NO, SIR.
I'LL HAVE TO BRING ABOARD
SOME OF THE DEBRIS
AND ANALYZE IT.
SCAN FOR THEIR DATA RECORDER.
IT MIGHT TELL US SOMETHING.
UNLESS I'M MISTAKEN,
THIS VIRUS IS A MUTATED FORM
OF THE LEVODIAN FLU.
IT'S IMMUNE TO WHATEVER
ANTIVIRAL WE'VE TRIED.
WE SHOULD CONTACT THE I.M.E.
THEY MAY HAVE SEEN
THIS MUTATION BEFORE.
I'M CERTAIN THEY'LL BE
WILLING TO SHARE THEIR
DATABASE WITH US.
I KNOW OF A FEW...
INDIRECT CHANNELS.
NO ONE WOULD HAVE TO KNOW.
THERE'S NO REASON
TO CONTACT THEM.
WE'VE ACQUIRED
THEIR ENTIRE DATABASE.
YOU STOLE IT.
MEDICAL RESEARCH ISN'T
A PRIORITY FOR THE HIGH COUNCIL.
I AM FORCED TO OBTAIN
INFORMATION HOWEVER I CAN.
THAT DOESN'T SOUND
VERY HONORABLE.
GIVEN THE CHOICE BETWEEN HONOR
AND SAVING LIVES,
I CHOOSE THE LATTER.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD ASK
YOUR SUPERIORS
TO STEAL
A GENOME SEQUENCER, MM?
WE'RE NOT GOING TO BE ABLE
TO MAP THE VIRUS
WITHOUT THE PROPER TECHNOLOGY.
THIS MAN'S BEEN INFECTED.
VERY OBSERVANT.
WE'RE BEING EXPOSED.
THIS PATIENT IS AT STAGE ONE.
THE VIRUS DOESN'T BECOME
CONTAGIOUS UNTIL STAGE THREE.
WHEN I ASKED YOU TO BRING ME
A SUBJECT FOR DISSECTION,
I ASSUMED
HE'D ALREADY BE DEAD.
HE WON'T BE ALIVE MUCH LONGER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
EUTHANIZING HIM.
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
COMMITTED TO SAVING LIVES.
IT IS MORE HONORABLE TO GIVE
ONE'S LIFE TO MEDICAL RESEARCH
THAN TO DIE FOR NO PURPOSE.
THAT CHOICE IS NOT OURS TO MAKE.
PROCEED.
COMPUTER, ESTABLISH
AN ENCRYPTED COM LINK.
STARFLEET FREQUENCY 79-BAKER.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
-LIEUTENANT.
-YOU TOLD ME THE KLINGONS
WERE GOING TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH THAT FREIGHTER,
-NOT DESTROY IT.
-I REGRET WHAT HAPPENED.
BUT THEY HAD
TO COVER THEIR TRACKS.
-HOW MANY WERE
ONBOARD THAT SHIP?
-THAT'S NOT YOUR CONCERN.
HAVE YOU ANALYZED
THE WEAPON SIGNATURES YET?
YES.
YOU HAVEN'T TOLD ARCHER?
BUT I'M NOT CERTAIN
HOW MUCH LONGER
I CAN KEEP THIS FROM HIM.
ORION RAIDERS HAVE BEEN
KNOWN TO OPERATE IN THIS AREA.
YOU WANT ME TO LIE AGAIN?
I COULD EXPLAIN THE SITUATION
TO THE CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE A PECULIAR SENSE
OF HUMOR, LIEUTENANT.
I'VE WORKED CLOSELY WITH
THE MAN. YOU CAN TRUST HIM.
ARCHER IS A STARFLEET CAPTAIN.
HIS DUTY WOULD BE TO REPORT
EVERYTHING YOU TELL HIM
TO ADMIRAL GARDNER.
THEY WOULD LAUNCH
AN INVESTIGATION.
I'M BEING COMPROMISED, SIR,
AND I DON'T LIKE IT.
THEN I SUGGEST YOU ADJUST YOUR
COMFORT LEVEL, LIEUTENANT.
YOU MADE A COMMITMENT TO US
LONG BEFORE YOU JOINED
THE ENTERPRISE.
[ RUMBLING, COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Tactical alert.
All hands to battle stations.
WHAT WAS THAT?
I BELIEVE WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
HULL PLATING'S HOLDING.
STILL NO RESPONSE.
TARGET THEIR WEAPONS.
WE'VE BEEN BOARDED.
"D" DECK, STARBOARD SIDE.
ACCESS TUBE 7.
SEAL IT OFF.
GET THE MACOs DOWN THERE.
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
DISABLE THAT SHIP.
I DON'T WANT THEM GETTING AWAY.
[ SPEAKS KLINGON ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THEY'VE ACTIVATED
THEIR TRANSPORTER.
THEY'RE GOING TO WARP.
PURSUIT COURSE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
THE HELM'S NOT RESPONDING.
WAKE HIM UP.
[ GRUNTING ]
WHY DID YOU ATTACK US?
[ SPEAKING KLINGON ]
"I HAVE NOTHING
TO SAY TO YOU, HUMAN."
-THAT SOUNDS LIKE --
-KLINGON.
THERE MUST BE
SOME KIND OF MISTAKE.
WHAT IS IT?
ACCORDING TO HIS BIO-SIGNATURE,
HE IS KLINGON.
HE MUST HAVE BEEN SURGICALLY
ALTERED TO LOOK HUMAN.
ANY THEORIES?
I NEED TO RUN FURTHER TESTS.
THEIR BOARDING PARTY DISABLED
OUR ANTIMATTER-FLOW REGULATORS.
WARP DRIVE SHOULD BE
REPAIRED IN SIX HOURS.
GIVE OUR NEW CHIEF ENGINEER
A HAND.
TELL HIM TO DIG
A LITTLE DEEPER
TO SEE IF THESE KLINGONS
DAMAGED ANY OTHER SYSTEMS.
THE RIGELIAN FREIGHTER --
DID YOU GET ANYTHING
OUT OF THE BLACK BOX?
IT'S BEEN ERASED.
IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN A SAFEGUARD,
IN CASE IT FELL
INTO THE WRONG HANDS.
WORK WITH HOSHI.
SEE IF YOU CAN
RECONSTRUCT ANY DATA.
THERE IS SOMETHING FAMILIAR
ABOUT THESE BASE-PAIR SEQUENCES.
FAMILIAR?
[ TARG GRUNTING ]
BOSHAR!
FEEDING TIME IS OVER.
GO BACK.
DO YOU THINK IT'S WISE
TO KEEP WILD ANIMALS IN HERE?
THERE ARE DOZENS OF CREATURES
IN YOUR SICK BAY.
I DON'T LET THEM ROAM FREE.
I COULD NEVER KEEP
BOSHAR LOCKED UP.
HE WAS MY FIRST PATIENT.
HE TORE HIS SIDE OPEN
WHEN I WAS A CHILD.
I STITCHED THE WOUND MYSELF.
I'VE SEEN
THESE SEQUENCES BEFORE --
SIX MONTHS AGO, TO BE PRECISE.
THIS IS AUGMENT DNA.
HOW DID MODIFIED HUMAN GENES
FIND THEIR WAY INTO THIS VIRUS?
IS THAT REALLY SUCH
A SURPRISE, DOCTOR?
IT ONLY TOOK TWO HUMAN AUGMENTS
TO COMMANDEER A BIRD-OF-PREY
AND MURDER ITS ENTIRE CREW.
THE EMPIRE COULD NOT ALLOW
AN INFERIOR SPECIES
TO GAIN AN ADVANTAGE ON US.
IMAGINE EVERY STARFLEET VESSEL
MANNED
WITH GENETICALLY ENGINEERED
HUMANS.
EARTH BANNED GENETIC ENGINEERING
DECADES AGO.
THE AUGMENTS WHO ATTACKED YOU
WERE RELICS OF ANOTHER ERA.
THE VULCANS TOLD THAT
TO THE HIGH COUNCIL.
THEY WEREN'T VERY PERSUASIVE.
WE WERE SIMPLY
RESPONDING TO A THREAT.
YOU WERE TRYING
TO CREATE KLINGON AUGMENTS.
BUT SOONG'S EXPERIMENTS
WERE ALL KILLED.
WHERE DID YOU GET
THE GENETIC MATERIAL?
SEVERAL EMBRYOS WERE FOUND
IN THE WRECKAGE
OF THE BIRD-OF-PREY.
WE USED THEM
TO RE-SEQUENCE
A NUMBER OF TEST SUBJECTS.
THERE WERE SOME
UNANTICIPATED SIDE EFFECTS.
THEIR CRANIAL RIDGES
STARTED TO DISSOLVE.
AUGMENT DNA WAS MORE AGGRESSIVE
THAN YOU REALIZED, HMM?
FOR A TIME, IT APPEARED
WE WERE QUITE SUCCESSFUL.
OUR AUGMENTS MIGHT HAVE LOOKED
HUMAN, BUT THEY WERE KLINGON.
STRONGER, MORE INTELLIGENT.
THEN THEIR NEURAL PATHWAYS
STARTED TO DEGRADE.
THEY DIED IN AGONY.
ONE OF THE TEST SUBJECTS WAS
SUFFERING FROM THE LEVODIAN FLU.
THE AUGMENT GENES
MODIFIED THE VIRUS.
IT BECAME AIRBORNE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
TOLD ME THIS EARLIER!
IF YOU HOPE TO
EVER LEAVE THIS PLACE,
I SUGGEST YOU STOP ASKING
QUESTIONS AND RESUME WORK.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WE MAY BE ABLE TO RECONSTRUCT
THE DIRECTORY
WITH A RECURSIVE ALGORITHM.
IS IT UNUSUAL TO HAVE WEIRD
DREAMS AFTER A MIND MELD?
SUBCONSCIOUS THOUGHTS
ARE OFTEN EXCHANGED.
THEY SOMETIMES
SURFACE DURING SLEEP.
I HAD A BIZARRE DREAM
LAST NIGHT.
COMMANDER TUCKER WAS IN IT.
WE WERE IN A STRANGE PLACE.
IT WAS ALL WHITE.
THERE WAS ALMOST, A, UH,
ROMANTIC QUALITY TO IT.
I DON'T EVER REMEMBER
DREAMING ABOUT COMMANDER TUCKER
BEFORE.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
MOST UNUSUAL.
THE RECORDER WAS ERASED
DELIBERATELY.
MALCOLM SAID THERE MIGHT HAVE
BEEN A SAFEGUARD.
THE MEMORY CORE WAS WIPED
BY THAT MICRODYNE COUPLER.
YOU'RE SURE?
IT LEFT A UNIQUE
MAGNETIC SIGNATURE.
WE FOUND IT
IN STORAGE LOCKER C-14.
THE LAST PERSON TO ACCESS THAT
LOCKER WAS LIEUTENANT REED.
I'M NOT QUITE SURE
WHAT YOU'RE GETTING AT, SIR.
ONLY SOMEONE
WITH SECURITY CLEARANCE
OF ALPHA-4 OR HIGHER
HAD ACCESS TO THE BLACK BOX.
THAT'S JUST T'POL,
YOU, AND ME.
I AGREE.
IT IS...A BIT OF A MYSTERY.
YOU'RE SURE
THAT FREIGHTER WAS DESTROYED
BY ORION WEAPONS?
THERE'S NO DOUBT.
I ASKED T'POL
TO DOUBLE-CHECK YOUR ANALYSIS.
THE FREIGHTER WAS FIRED ON
BY KLINGON DISRUPTORS.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
IT MUST HAVE BEEN A MISTAKE.
I'VE SEEN THE SENSOR LOGS.
SOMEONE COULD HAVE
TAMPERED WITH THEM.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON.
ANSWER ME, LIEUTENANT.
RESPECTFULLY, SIR,
I REFUSE TO ANSWER
ANY MORE QUESTIONS.
MALCOLM...
I NEVER WOULD'VE BELIEVED
THAT YOU,
OF ALL PEOPLE...
CORPORAL.
LIEUTENANT REED'S
BEEN RELIEVED OF DUTY.
ESCORT HIM TO THE BRIG
AND CONFINE HIM.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WE'VE SET COURSE
FOR KLINGON TERRITORY.
WE HAVEN'T PICKED UP
ANY WARP SIGNATURES YET.
I MAY HAVE TO TAKE
THIS SHIP INTO THEIR SPACE.
I DON'T HAVE TO TELL YOU
HOW DANGEROUS THAT IS.
IF YOU KNOW WHERE
THEY'VE TAKEN PHLOX --
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE THE DOCTOR IS, CAPTAIN.
ON THAT, YOU HAVE MY WORD.
YOUR WORD ISN'T WORTH
A LOT AT THE MOMENT.
THE MALCOLM REED I KNOW
WOULD GIVE HIS LIFE
BEFORE COMMITTING TREASON.
I'M NOT WORKING
FOR THE KLINGONS.
WHO, THEN?
YOU'VE BETRAYED EVERYTHING
THAT UNIFORM STANDS FOR.
CAPTAIN!
THERE ARE SOME...OBLIGATIONS...
THAT GO BEYOND
MY LOYALTY TO YOU
AND THIS CREW.
WHAT THE HELL DOES THAT MEAN?
I CAN'T SAY ANY MORE.
YOU HAVEN'T SAID
MUCH OF ANYTHING.
YOU'VE TOLD ME
A LOT ABOUT YOUR FATHER --
HIS YEARS IN THE ROYAL NAVY,
THEIR TRADITION OF
HONOR AND SERVICE.
HOW DO YOU THINK HE'LL REACT
WHEN HE LEARNS YOU'RE
FACING COURT-MARTIAL?
[ Voice breaking ]
I WOULDN'T KNOW, SIR.
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
I CAN'T SEQUENCE
THESE NUCLEOTIDES ANY FASTER.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD HAVE
ABDUCTED DR. SOONG.
HE COULD HAVE MAPPED THIS GENOME
MORE EFFICIENTLY THAN I CAN.
WE TRIED.
SOONG WAS UNDER HEAVY GUARD.
IF YOU DON'T
ACCELERATE YOUR EFFORTS,
THERE WILL BE
NO ONE LEFT TO CURE.
THE HIGH COUNCIL
HAS DISPATCHED THE FLEET.
THEY HAVE ANNIHILATED
N'VAK COLONY.
N'VAK WAS ONE OF THE FIRST
PLANETS AFFECTED BY THE PLAGUE.
THEY'RE MASSACRING
THE VICTIMS?
THE COUNCIL WILL DO
WHATEVER IS REQUIRED
TO CONTAIN THIS OUTBREAK.
GENERAL,
WE ARE MAKING PROGRESS,
BUT I'LL NEED A FEW WEEKS
TO DEVELOP AN ANTIVIRAL AGENT.
IT WILL HAVE TO BE TESTED.
MILLIONS WILL BE
INFECTED BY THEN.
THE COUNCIL WILL NOT WAIT.
HOW LONG UNTIL THE FLEET
REACHES US?
-FIVE DAYS.
-I CAN'T CURE THIS
IN FIVE DAYS!
THEY WOULDN'T DESTROY US
IF THEY KNEW WE HAD CREATED
KLINGON AUGMENTS.
THE EXPERIMENT FAILED.
IT SUCCEEDED
FOR A BRIEF PERIOD.
IF PHLOX AND I CAN FIND A WAY
TO STABILIZE THE HUMAN DNA
PRIOR TO THE ONSET
OF STAGE THREE,
OUR AUGMENTS WOULD SURVIVE.
IF WE'RE SUCCESSFUL, YOU COULD
USE THEM AS LEVERAGE,
FORCE THE HIGH COUNCIL TO GIVE
US MORE TIME TO FIND A CURE.
YOU DON'T SERIOUSLY EXPECT ME
TO HELP YOU
CREATE KLINGON AUGMENTS?
YOU COULD SAVE THE INHABITANTS
OF THIS PLANET.
I WON'T ASSIST YOU.
KILL ME IF YOU...MUST.
I REFUSE TO COOPERATE.
TAKE HIM.
HAIL THE DOCK MASTER.
THIS IS CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ.
REQUEST PERMISSION TO DEPART.
You're cleared for departure.
Smooth sailing, Columbia.
THANK YOU.
BRIDGE TO ENGINEERING.
Are we ready, Mr. Tucker?
JUST A FEW MORE SECONDS.
I HOPE.
ENSIGN.
DILITHIUM MATRIX IS STABLE.
DRIVER COILS ARE CONFIGURED
FOR WARP SPEED.
NICE WORK.
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
WE'RE READY
WHENEVER YOU ARE, CAPTAIN.
TIME TO WEIGH ANCHOR.
LIEUTENANT,
AFT THRUSTERS AT ONE-HALF
UNTIL WE CLEAR SPACEDOCK.
THEN TAKE US TO WARP.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ COUGHING ]
SO, WHAT ARE YOU IN FOR?
IS YOUR CAPTAIN HOPING YOU'LL
OBTAIN INFORMATION FROM ME?
I SHOULDN'T THINK SO.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
THAT'S A LONG STORY.
ENTERTAIN ME.
I LIED TO HIM.
YOU'RE FORTUNATE TO BE ALIVE.
A KLINGON WHO BETRAYS
HIS CAPTAIN
WOULD BE IMMEDIATELY EXECUTED.
[ COUGHS ]
WHY DID YOU AND YOUR MEN
BOARD ENTERPRISE?
YOU KNOW, YOU MAY FIND THIS
HARD TO BELIEVE,
BUT YOU AND I ACTUALLY
WANT THE SAME THING.
AND WHAT IS THAT?
A CURE.
THERE'S NO REASON FOR YOU
OR ANY MORE OF YOUR PEOPLE
TO DIE.
-[ RUMBLING ]
-[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THERE'S A MALFUNCTION
IN THE INTERMIX CHAMBER.
PLASMA PRESSURE'S RISING.
THE ANTIMATTER-FLOW REGULATORS
ARE LOCKED OPEN.
-DID THE KLINGONS DAMAGE THEM?
-UNCERTAIN.
PRESSURE'S
APPROACHING CRITICAL.
CAN WE DROP TO IMPULSE?
THE REACTOR WOULD BREACH.
BUT WE CAN REDUCE PRESSURE
BY INCREASING SPEED.
GO TO MAXIMUM WARP.
GET DOWN TO ENGINEERING.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN DO.
YOU SABOTAGED US.
HOW DO WE REPAIR THE DAMAGE?
IF OUR REACTOR BREACHES,
YOU'RE GOING TO DIE WITH US.
I'M A SOLDIER OF THE EMPIRE.
I'M PREPARED TO DIE.
CAPTAIN, YOU NEED
YOUR TACTICAL OFFICER!
PLEASE, SIR!
I CAN BE USEFUL!
COMMANDER, DID YOU SEE THAT?
PLEASE BE MORE SPECIFIC.
ON THE MONITOR.
T'POL TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
Go ahead.
THE WARP MATRIX
HAS BEEN COMPROMISED
-by a Klingon subroutine.
-CAN YOU REMOVE IT?
I'm not certain.
It's infiltrated
our command protocols.
DO WHAT YOU CAN.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-Bridge to Captain Archer.
Pressure's increasing again.
TAKE US TO WARP 5.2.
SIR, WE CAN'T HOLD
THAT SPEED FOR LONG.
We're out of options, Travis.
5.2.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]