PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
YOU, DENOBULAN.
COME WITH US.
[ GRUNTING ]
THE VIRUS IS SPREADING
FROM PLANET TO PLANET.
-MILLIONS ARE ALREADY INFECTED.
-WHAT DO YOU WANT WITH ME?
IF THIS CONTINUES, THE KLINGON
SPECIES WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
THERE'S A JOB
THAT NEEDS DOING, LIEUTENANT.
IT MAY BE THE ONLY WAY
TO SAVE YOUR FRIEND'S LIFE.
YOU DON'T SERIOUSLY EXPECT ME
TO HELP YOU CREATE
KLINGON AUGMENTS?
TAKE HIM.
THE MALCOLM REED I KNOW
WOULD GIVE HIS LIFE
BEFORE COMMITTING TREASON.
THERE ARE SOME...OBLIGATIONS...
THAT GO BEYOND
MY LOYALTY TO YOU
AND THIS CREW.
-T'Pol to Captain Archer.
-Go ahead.
The warp matrix
has been compromised
by a Klingon subroutine.
IT'S INFILTRATED
OUR COMMAND PROTOCOLS.
PRESSURE'S INCREASING AGAIN.
TAKE US TO WARP 5.2.
SIR, WE CAN'T HOLD
THAT SPEED FOR LONG.
We're out of options, Travis.
5.2.
AND NOW THE CONCLUSION.
[ RUMBLING ]
WE HAVE 47 MINUTES
UNTIL OUR REACTOR BREACHES.
WHAT DID THE KLINGONS DO TO IT?
THEY ALTERED OUR
ENGINEERING SUBROUTINES.
IF WE GO BELOW WARP 5,
THE REACTOR'S GOING TO EXPLODE.
HOW CAN I HELP?
I'VE JUST BEEN TALKING
WITH TRIP.
COLUMBIA CAN RENDEZVOUS
WITH US IN 30 MINUTES.
HE SAYS HE CAN
RESTORE THE SUBROUTINES.
HE CAN'T DO THAT
FROM COLUMBIA.
WE'RE GONNA BRING HIM ONBOARD.
THE TRANSPORTER
WON'T OPERATE AT WARP,
AND DOCKING'S OUT
OF THE QUESTION.
TRIP TOLD ME
YOU HAVE EXPERIENCE
TRANSFERRING PERSONNEL
AT WARP SPEED.
IN TRAINING EXERCISES, YES,
BUT AT WARP SPEED 1.
EVERY MOVE WAS REHEARSED
IN SIMULATORS FOR WEEKS.
WE DON'T HAVE WEEKS.
WE'LL HAVE TO MERGE OUR
WARP FIELD WITH COLUMBIA'S.
T'POL'S DOING
THE CALCULATIONS NOW.
AT WARP 5, WE'LL HAVE TO MOVE
WITHIN 50 METERS OF EACH OTHER.
HAS ANYONE
EVER DONE THIS BEFORE?
TRAVIS CAN HANDLE THE FLYING.
CAN YOU GET TRIP OVER HERE?
[ RUMBLING ]
YOU'LL HAVE TO LET ME OUT
OF THIS BRIG.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-COMMANDER TUCKER.
Are you ready for this?
AS READY AS I'LL EVER BE.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
Columbia to Enterprise.
THIS IS ARCHER.
We're matching speed
and trajectory as requested.
STAND BY, COLUMBIA.
ARCHER TO REED.
GO AHEAD.
We're in position.
HAVE THEM START
THEIR ROTATION.
COMING UP ON 100 METERS.
90. 80 METERS.
THIS IS THE BRIDGE.
ALL HANDS BRACE FOR
WARP-FIELD CONTACT.
HOLD HER STEADY, TRAVIS,
or Chef will know who to blame
for the mess in the galley.
WE'RE AT 50 METERS
AND HOLDING.
MAKE SURE EVERYTHING'S READY
FOR TRIP IN ENGINEERING.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-ARCHER TO REED.
YOU'RE ALL CLEAR.
-Understood.
COLUMBIA,
I'M DEPLOYING THE TETHER.
NICE SHOOTING, MALCOLM.
TUCKER TO CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ.
-Go ahead.
-I'M HEADING OUT.
Quick as you can, Commander.
[ SIGHS ]
NEVER THOUGHT I'D SEE
THE STARS LIKE THIS.
EYES ON THE CABLE, COMMANDER.
I NEED YOU BACK HERE
IN ONE PIECE.
YOU'RE DOING FINE, TRIP.
[ RUMBLING ]
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
T'POL, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
I'M READING A FLUCTUATION
IN THE WARP FIELD.
Take power from life support
if you have to,
BUT KEEP THE FIELD CONSTANT.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
SIR, I'M HAVING TROUBLE
HOLDING POSITION.
52 METERS, 55.
DON'T MEAN TO BE A PEST,
BUT COULD SOMEONE TELL ME
WHAT'S GOING ON?
YOU'RE ALMOST HERE, TRIP.
KEEP GOING.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
ENGINEERING, REPORT!
I'M REROUTING POWER NOW,
CAPTAIN. STAND BY.
59 METERS.
THE TETHER'S AT ITS LIMIT!
HURRY UP!
T'POL TO THE BRIDGE.
IT'S NOT WORKING.
THE FIELD IS STILL
FLUCTUATING.
ALMOST THERE!
PERMISSION TO COME ABOARD?
BRIDGE, I HAVE HIM.
YOU ALL RIGHT, TRIP?
I'LL FEEL A LOT BETTER
WHEN THIS IS OVER.
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY TO DO THIS,
CAPTAIN -- A COLD START.
I HAVE TO SHUT DOWN THE REACTOR
AND RESET THE ALGORITHMS.
ONCE WE BRING
THE WARP ENGINE BACK ONLINE,
THE SUBROUTINES SHOULD BE
BACK TO NORMAL.
BUT IF WE SHUT DOWN
THE REACTOR --
That's why we need to move
inside Columbia's warp field.
THEY CAN SUSTAIN OUR SPEED WHILE
I REINITIALIZE THE ENGINES.
THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO HOLD US
FOR MORE THAN A MINUTE OR TWO.
THEY DON'T HAVE ENOUGH POWER.
I'VE GOT A SHORTCUT IN MIND.
SHORTCUT?
THOSE SUBROUTINES
WOULD TAKE HOURS TO DECRYPT.
BETTER JUST TO PURGE THEM,
WIPE THEM CLEAN.
I'LL CONTACT COLUMBIA.
WHAT ARE THEY HERE FOR?
THE CAPTAIN AND I HAVE HAD
A SLIGHT MISUNDERSTANDING.
HOW SLIGHT?
THESE GENTLEMEN ARE HERE
TO ESCORT ME BACK TO THE BRIG.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL TELL YOU ALL ABOUT IT
WHEN WE'RE NOT QUITE SO BUSY.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
FANCY MEETING YOU HERE.
INTERMIX PRESSURE?
1527.
-FIELD VARIANCE?
-87 MILLICOCHRANES.
SOMEBODY HASN'T BEEN TAKING
VERY GOOD CARE OF MY ENGINE.
SPEAK WITH THE KLINGONS.
-WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
-YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAKE NOTES.
I'M ABOUT TO PERFORM
A MANUAL SHUTDOWN AND RESTART
IN LESS THAN TWO MINUTES.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
WATCH ME.
-COLUMBIA TO ENTERPRISE.
-GO AHEAD.
I've routed everything I've got
to my warp field.
DO ME A FAVOR, JONATHAN.
MAKE THIS QUICK.
ARCHER TO TRIP.
READY WHEN YOU ARE.
STAND BY! EVERYONE GET AWAY
FROM THE BULKHEADS!
IT'S GONNA GET
A LITTLE HOT IN HERE!
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
REACTOR SHUT DOWN IN 5, 4,
3, 2, 1!
T'POL, PRIME THE INJECTORS.
-JENKINS, MAN THE RELAYS.
-YES, SIR.
COLUMBIA TO ENTERPRISE.
YOU'VE GOT ABOUT 40 SECONDS.
UNDERSTOOD.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-Trip, how's it going?
-JUST ANOTHER MINUTE, CAPTAIN.
-You don't have a minute!
GET READY TO INITIALIZE
THE MATRIX.
ENTERPRISE,
WE'RE LOSING THE FIELD.
15 SECONDS, TRIP.
ALMOST THERE.
FULL POWER TO CONTAINMENT.
FIRE UP THE ANTIMATTER STREAM.
10 seconds.
9, 8, 7, 6...
-COMMANDER!
-HERE WE GO!
-...5, 4...
3, 2...
[ ENGINES WHOOSH ]
WE'VE GOT WARP POWER.
ENGINEERING TO THE BRIDGE.
SUBROUTINES HAVE BEEN PURGED.
Appreciate the house call,
Mr. Tucker.
ANYTIME.
I'D LIKE TO DROP TO IMPULSE
FOR A WHILE, CAPTAIN,
-just to check things over.
-STAND BY.
ENTERPRISE TO COLUMBIA.
THANKS FOR THE LIFT.
YOU'RE NOT GETTING AWAY WITH
MY CHIEF ENGINEER THAT EASILY.
ANY PLANS FOR THE NEXT FEW DAYS?
WHAT'VE YOU GOT IN MIND?
PHLOX.
PHLOX?
THIS WILL HELP.
[ GRUNTS ]
MY APOLOGIES
FOR THE GENERAL'S CONDUCT.
SO CRUEL! THIS IS NO WAY
TO TREAT A MAN OF SCIENCE!
[ PANTING ]
THEN END IT.
CONTACT STARFLEET.
MY PEOPLE NEED YOU, PHLOX.
WE HAVE NO HEALERS
WITH YOUR ABILITIES.
YOU WANT ME TO CREATE
KLINGON AUGMENTS,
LIVING WEAPONS.
I WON'T DO IT.
NO, NO.
I'VE BEEN REVIEWING YOUR WORK.
IT'S BRILLIANT!
YOU HAVE DISCOVERED A WEAKNESS
IN THE VIRUS CAUSING THE PLAGUE.
IF WE INTERRUPT THE
TRANSCRIPTION SEQUENCE HERE...
YES. YES.
THAT WOULD STOP
THE GENETIC EFFECTS
OF THE VIRUS IN STAGE ONE.
THERE'D BE CHANGES
OF APPEARANCE,
SOME MINOR NEURAL REORDERING,
BUT NO DEVELOPMENT
OF STAGE-TWO CHARACTERISTICS.
NO ENHANCED STRENGTH
OR SPEED OR ENDURANCE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BUT THEN GENERAL K'VAGH
WOULD NOT GET HIS AUGMENTS.
HE WOULD NEVER ALLOW IT.
WHAT IF WE DON'T TELL HIM?
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IF THE GENERAL LEARNS
THAT WE'VE DECEIVED HIM?
THE CURE WOULD SAVE
MILLIONS OF INNOCENT LIVES.
WHAT MORE HONORABLE DEATH
COULD THERE BE FOR A HEALER,
KLINGON OR DENOBULAN?
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
I'VE ASKED COLUMBIA TO JOIN US
IN OUR SEARCH FOR PHLOX.
WE'LL HAVE A BETTER CHANCE
OF MAKING IT
THROUGH KLINGON TERRITORY
WITH TWICE THE FIREPOWER.
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU CAN TELL ME
WHERE I'M GOING THIS TIME?
NO, I DIDN'T THINK SO.
THOSE ARE MY PERSONAL FILES.
NOT WHEN THEY AFFECT MY SHIP!
T'POL RESTORED EVERYTHING
YOU TRIED TO ERASE.
WE RAN HIS FACE AND VOICEPRINT
THROUGH OUR DATABASE.
HIS NAME'S HARRIS.
HE WORKED IN STARFLEET SECURITY
UP TILL FIVE YEARS AGO.
AFTER THAT, HIS FILE ENDS.
CAPTAIN, THERE'S NOTHING MORE
I CAN ADD.
I WON'T ACCEPT THAT!
YOU ENDANGERED
EVERY MEMBER OF THIS CREW.
YOU ANSWER TO ME.
I THOUGHT I KNEW YOU, MALCOLM.
WHATEVER HOLD THIS HARRIS HAS
ON YOU,
-YOU COULD'VE COME TO ME.
-I'M UNDER ORDERS.
I'M YOUR COMMANDING OFFICER!
IF YOU DON'T TELL ME WHAT'S
GOING ON, I'LL GO TO STARFLEET.
WHATEVER YOU THINK YOU'VE BEEN
TRYING TO KEEP HIDDEN
IS GOING TO COME OUT --
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
I CAN'T TELL YOU
WHAT I DON'T KNOW.
THEN LET ME TALK
TO SOMEONE WHO CAN.
SEND A MESSAGE TO HARRIS.
HAS THE HOUSE OF PHLOX
ALWAYS BEEN ONE OF HEALERS?
THERE IS NO, UH,
HOUSE OF PHLOX.
DENOBULAN FAMILY UNITS
ARE DIFFERENT FROM KLINGONS'.
AH, YES, I'VE HEARD.
THREE WIVES FOR EACH HUSBAND.
THREE HUSBANDS FOR EACH WIFE.
YOUR MATING PRACTICES
MUST BE VERY COMPLEX.
WONDROUSLY SO.
WHAT ABOUT THE HOUSE OF ANTAAK?
WE ARE A WARRIOR CASTE.
WHEN I BECAME A HEALER,
MY FATHER DISOWNED ME.
AS A PHYSICIAN
IN THE IMPERIAL FLEET,
YOU'VE SERVED IN THE MILITARY.
NOT AS WELL AS I SHOULD HAVE.
I DID NOT SCREEN
MY SUBJECTS PROPERLY.
THIS PLAGUE, ALL ITS VICTIMS...
IT'S MY FAULT.
MY FAILURE IS
THE REASON YOU'RE HERE.
THE HUMANS COULD NOT STOP US.
I AM YOUR SUPERIOR.
YOU WILL SALUTE.
NOW, REPORT.
ENTERPRISE WAS DESTROYED.
STARFLEET WILL THINK
IT WAS HER ENGINES.
ONE OF YOU IS MISSING.
YOUR SON WAS SLOW.
THE HUMANS KILLED HIM.
DID HE DIE WITH HONOR?
HE LET HUMANS KILL HIM.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
REPORT.
DR. PHLOX HAS MADE
EXCELLENT PROGRESS.
DETAILS.
I'VE IDENTIFIED
THE RNA SEQUENCES THAT CODE --
DETAILS I CAN PASS ON
TO MY SUPERIORS.
I KNOW WHERE TO LOOK
FOR THE SWITCH THAT WILL
TURN OFF THE VIRUS.
HOW LONG UNTIL YOU FIND IT?
AN HOUR.
ONE HOUR.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I HAVE NEWS
FOR THE HIGH COUNCIL.
EXPLAIN.
THE DENOBULAN IS CLOSE
TO PERFECTING THE
AUGMENTS' GENOME.
THE COUNCIL HAS
SHUT DOWN YOUR PROJECT.
IF YOU STERILIZE THIS COLONY,
THEN ALL OUR RESEARCH
WILL BE LOST.
THE FLEET WILL REACH YOU
IN THREE DAYS.
IF YOU'RE SUCCESSFUL
BY THE TIME WE GET TO ORBIT,
QU'VAT WILL BE SPARED.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
CAPTAIN,
IT'S GONNA BE A WHILE
BEFORE EVERYTHING'S BACK
TO NORMAL IN ENGINEERING.
CAN KELBY HANDLE IT?
[ SIGHS ]
I COULD PULL A LITTLE DOUBLE
DUTY TO HELP HIM OUT.
I COULD CHECK
WITH CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ.
SOMETHING ELSE?
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON WITH MALCOLM?
NOTHING I CAN GET INTO
RIGHT NOW.
FAIR ENOUGH.
GUESS I'D BETTER
GET BACK TO COLUMBIA.
I'LL WALK WITH YOU.
ARE YOU ENJOYING YOUR TIME
ABOARD COLUMBIA?
SURE, WHY WOULDN'T I?
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN EXPERIENCING
ANY PROBLEMS?
SUCH AS?
ADJUSTING TO NEW FOOD,
NEW ROUTINES...
TROUBLE SLEEPING.
I SLEEP JUST FINE.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
FINE.
YOU SURE ABOUT THAT?
QUITE.
YOUR HOUR IS UP.
WE ARE GETTING
THE TEST RESULTS NOW.
WE ARE RUNNING OUT OF TIME!
GENERAL, I KNOW THE KLINGON
FLEET IS ON ITS WAY,
AND I UNDERSTAND WHAT THIS
PROJECT COST YOU, PERSONALLY.
ANTAAK TOLD ME ABOUT YOUR SON.
HE DIED IN COMBAT
FOR THE EMPIRE.
AT LEAST HE WAS SPARED THE FINAL
STAGE OF THIS DISEASE.
MAY I, UH, ASK
HOW HE WAS INFECTED?
COMMAND CHOSE HIS UNIT
FOR THE AUGMENT EXPERIMENT
WHEN WE HAD EXHAUSTED
OUR SUPPLY OF PRISONERS.
MY SON WAS A WARRIOR.
HE ASKED FOR NO SPECIAL
TREATMENT, AND I GAVE HIM NONE.
[ TRAY CLATTERS ]
[ SCOFFS ]
WHAT'D THEY GIVE YOU?
IT'S DEAD. I CAN'T EAT THAT.
NO WONDER YOU'RE ALL SO WEAK.
PHYSICAL STRENGTH
ISN'T EVERYTHING.
WELL, YOU CAN'T
WIN WARS WITHOUT IT.
BEING SMART IS MORE IMPORTANT.
GENERAL SUN TZU SAID
THAT THE GREATEST VICTORIES
ARE THOSE WON
WITHOUT FIGHTING.
THE GREAT KAHLESS SAID THERE'S
NO VICTORY WITHOUT COMBAT.
DO YOU EVER QUESTION
WHY YOU FIGHT?
SOLDIERS DON'T QUESTION.
THEY OBEY.
WHAT IF YOUR SUPERIORS
ARE WRONG?
THEY'RE IMPRISONED...OR KILLED.
THAT'S NOT HOW WE DO THINGS
IN STARFLEET.
WHICH IS WHY THE KLINGON EMPIRE
WILL DEFEAT YOU.
THEN HOW COME YOU'RE
IN THE SAME BRIG THAT I'M IN?
YOU SAID WE'D BECOME STRONGER.
THIS IS WHAT
YOU'VE DONE TO US.
HE WILL BECOME INFECTIOUS,
SO HE SHOULD BE QUARANTINED.
WE'LL REMAIN HERE.
IF WE'RE GOING TO DIE, WE'LL DIE
TOGETHER AS COMRADES.
BE PATIENT, LIEUTENANT.
THE DENOBULAN IS WORKING
TO STABILIZE THE HUMAN DNA.
YOU WILL ALL BE HEALTHY AGAIN
AND STRONGER THAN ANY KLINGON.
WILL HE RESTORE
OUR APPEARANCE?
I DON'T KNOW.
HOW DO YOU EXPECT US TO
RETURN HOME LOOKING LIKE THIS?
WE WILL BE OUTCASTS.
THERE WILL BE NO PLACE
FOR US IN THE EMPIRE.
YOUR HEART IS STILL KLINGON.
ARE YOU CERTAIN OF THAT?
DURING THE BATTLE
WITH THE STARFLEET SHIP,
I FELT FEAR FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE I WAS A CHILD.
I WASN'T ALONE.
I COULD SEE IT IN THE EYES
OF THE OTHERS.
WE'VE BECOME LIKE THEM.
WEAK, COWARDLY.
IT WOULD BE BETTER
FOR US TO DIE.
AS LONG AS I DRAW BREATH,
THE EMPIRE WILL NOT
TURN ITS BACK ON YOU.
I GET THE FEELING
YOU MISS PHLOX, TOO.
MAYBE IT'S JUST THE STASH OF
CHEESE HE'S GOT IN SICK BAY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
HOLD THAT THOUGHT.
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
I'M TOLD YOU HAVE
SOME QUESTIONS FOR ME.
WHERE'S MY DOCTOR?
HE'S SAFE,
ON A MISSION OF GREAT
IMPORTANCE TO STARFLEET.
PHLOX WAS KIDNAPPED.
STARFLEET WOULD
NEVER AUTHORIZE THAT.
REREAD THE CHARTER --
ARTICLE 14, SECTION 31.
THERE ARE A FEW LINES
THAT MAKE ALLOWANCES
FOR BENDING THE RULES DURING
TIMES OF EXTRAORDINARY THREAT.
WHAT THREAT?
TAKE YOUR PICK.
EARTH'S GOT A LOT OF ENEMIES.
KLINGONS ATTACKED MY SHIP. IS
THAT WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT I WANT TO TALK ABOUT
IS LIEUTENANT REED.
HE'S DONE GOOD WORK
FOR US OVER THE YEARS.
DON'T BE TOO HARD ON HIM.
HE WAS JUST FOLLOWING
MY ORDERS.
YOU PUT HIM
IN AN IMPOSSIBLE POSITION.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY YOU
WOULD FEEL THAT WAY,
BUT THIS IS BIGGER
THAN ONE CAPTAIN AND ONE SHIP.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO DO BETTER THAN THAT.
ALL I CAN TELL YOU IS
THAT IF YOU INTERFERE
BEFORE PHLOX COMPLETES
HIS ASSIGNMENT,
THE REPERCUSSIONS WILL
AFFECT ENTIRE WORLDS.
ONE OF THESE FOUR STRAINS
HAS THE GENETIC TRIGGER
THAT CAN NEUTRALIZE THE VIRUS
BEFORE IT ADVANCES
TO ITS LETHAL STAGE.
-WHICH ONE?
-I DON'T KNOW YET.
THAT'S WHY I HAVE
TO CHECK EACH OF THEM.
-HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE?
-A WEEK.
YOUR FLEET CAN QUARANTINE
THIS WORLD, HMM,
WHILE I COMPLETE MY TESTS.
STERILIZATION IS NOT NECESSARY.
FLEET ADMIRAL KRELL
WILL NOT EXTEND HIS DEADLINE.
THE ONLY POSSIBLE WAY TO GET
RESULTS ON KRELL'S SCHEDULE
IS TO INFECT
FOUR HEALTHY KLINGONS.
YOU HAVE FOUR RIGHT HERE!
ONLY ONE OF THESE STRAINS
WILL WORK.
THE OTHER THREE WILL BE LETHAL.
ETHICALLY, IT'S UNTHINKABLE!
THE ETHICS, DOCTOR, ARE SIMPLE.
THREE LIVES TO SAVE MILLIONS.
AT FIRST,
IT DIDN'T SEEM LIKE LYING.
WHAT ELSE WOULD YOU CALL IT?
COVERT OPERATIONS.
I WAS A YOUNG ENSIGN.
IT WAS...EXCITING.
HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT IT NOW?
I THOUGHT IT WAS DONE.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
THAT HARRIS HAS CONTACTED ME
SINCE I'VE SERVED ON ENTERPRISE.
HE TOLD ME ABOUT THE PLAGUE.
HE SAID THEY NEEDED PHLOX TO
HELP THE KLINGONS FIND A CURE.
I WAS SUPPOSED
TO JUST SLOW US DOWN.
DID HARRIS TELL YOU ABOUT THIS?
I HAD T'POL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK
AT OUR PRISONER'S MEDICAL SCANS.
IT'S HUMAN DNA.
I'M GUESSING THE PLAGUE
IS A SIDE EFFECT
OF A MILITARY EXPERIMENT
THAT WENT WRONG.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
HARRIS CLAIMS HE'S DOING THIS
BECAUSE STARFLEET NEEDS
A STABLE KLINGON EMPIRE.
DO YOU BELIEVE HIM?
I DON'T TRUST HIM.
IF THE KLINGONS NEEDED OUR HELP,
THERE ARE EASIER WAYS TO GET IT.
I WANTED TO TELL YOU EVERYTHING,
CAPTAIN.
THERE'S A WAY OUT OF THIS.
I DON'T HAVE TO PUT YOU
BACK IN THE BRIG,
BUT YOU HAVE TO CHOOSE
WHERE YOUR LOYALTIES LIE.
I WASN'T TOLD
WHERE PHLOX WAS TAKEN,
BUT STARFLEET INTELLIGENCE
BELIEVES THE KLINGONS HAVE
A GENETIC RESEARCH FACILITY
ON QU'VAT COLONY.
AS YOU WERE.
HOW LONG UNTIL
WE REACH QU'VAT?
SIX HOURS, SIR.
CAPTAIN, WE NEED TO BE READY
FOR KLINGON PATROLS.
I SUGGEST THAT COLUMBIA
WITHDRAWS TO A SAFER DISTANCE,
SO THAT WE DON'T
MAKE A SINGLE TARGET.
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ.
WHY DID YOU THINK YOU'D
SUCCEED IN PERFECTING AUGMENTS
WHEN DR. SOONG FAILED?
SOONG'S MISTAKE WAS THAT
HE MADE TOO FEW OF THEM.
EARTH ONCE HAD THOUSANDS.
THEY BECAME TYRANNICAL
AND STARTED A WAR.
-KLINGONS HAVE DISCIPLINE.
-AUGMENTS DON'T.
THEIR INCREASED AGGRESSION
IS MATCHED BY THEIR
DECREASED INHIBITIONS.
YOU'D LOSE CONTROL OF THEM,
JUST AS HUMANS DID.
HOW LONG UNTIL WE KNOW
WHICH ONE OF US SURVIVES?
AN HOUR, AT MOST.
WOULD BLOODWINE
AFFECT THE RESULTS?
I DON'T BELIEVE SO.
THEN WE SHALL DRINK...
[ LAUGHS ]
...TO THE BRAVERY
OF THESE WARRIORS.
DOCTOR!
NEVER ON THE JOB.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WE KNOW PHLOX WAS TAKEN TO
QU'VAT COLONY TO WORK ON A CURE.
WE'RE GONNA BE THERE
IN LESS THAN AN HOUR.
[ COUGHING ]
KRELL'S PATROLS
WILL CRUSH YOU.
THEY'VE ALL BEEN RECALLED
TO ENFORCE QUARANTINE ZONES.
PHLOX WILL BE IN
THE MEDICAL FACILITY.
WE NEED THE COORDINATES.
[ COUGHS ]
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO HELP US,
HELP YOUR PEOPLE.
MY BROTHERS.
THEY'RE QUITE ILL.
SO ARE YOU.
TRY TO REST.
DOCTOR.
THE TWO GUARDS ARE DISPLAYING
THE FIRST SYMPTOMS.
THAT ACCOUNTS FOR TWO
OF THE THREE LETHAL STRAINS.
SO EITHER GENERAL K'VAGH LIVES,
OR I DO.
[ SCANNER BEEPS ]
IT'S THE GENERAL, ISN'T IT?
HIS STRAIN HAS THE CURE.
IF WE WORK QUICKLY, THERE'S A
CHANCE WE CAN TREAT YOU IN TIME.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WHAT NOW?
THERE'S BEEN A COMPLICATION.
ANOTHER ONE?
THIS TIME, YOUR PEOPLE
FAILED TO STOP ENTERPRISE.
IT'S ON ITS WAY TO QU'VAT,
WITH COLUMBIA.
ORDER THEM TO WITHDRAW.
YOU KNOW I DON'T HAVE
THAT AUTHORITY.
THEN I'LL DESTROY THEM.
WE HAD AN ARRANGEMENT.
YOU DID WHAT I WANTED.
I DON'T NEED YOU ANYMORE.
YOU AGREED THAT BOTH
OUR GOVERNMENTS WOULD BENEFIT
IF THE TWO OF US
WORKED TOGETHER.
AND YOU BELIEVED ME.
LOAD THE AMINO ACIDS.
I'LL EXTRACT THE VIRAL DNA
FROM HIS BLOOD.
CAPTAIN.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
BETTER, NOW THAT YOU'RE HERE.
FATHER.
I WAS TOLD
THAT YOU HAD BEEN KILLED.
THE HUMANS SPARED ME.
-I CAME TO GET MY DOCTOR BACK.
-WE NEED HIM HERE.
I HAVE TWO SHIPS IN ORBIT,
HEAVILY ARMED.
GENTLEMEN, PLEASE.
I THINK I CAN SPEAK FOR MYSELF.
CAPTAIN.
I NEED A LITTLE MORE TIME
TO CURE THIS PLAGUE.
CURE?
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO PERFECT
THE AUGMENT GENOME!
I LIED.
YOUR SON MAY BE ALIVE,
BUT HE WILL NOT SURVIVE
MUCH LONGER
UNLESS I COMPLETE MY WORK.
A FEW HOURS, CAPTAIN --
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
SEVERAL MILLION PATIENTS
ARE COUNTING ON IT.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
-COMMANDER.
THREE KLINGON BATTLE CRUISERS
HAVE JUST DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
OPEN A CHANNEL TO COLUMBIA.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
THE KLINGONS ARE
JAMMING EVERYTHING.
[ ALARM BLARING ]
WHAT IS IT?
-KRELL'S SHIPS ARE HERE.
-KEEP WORKING.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
TELL THE KLINGONS
WE HAVE THE CURE.
ENTERPRISE, RESPOND.
This is Fleet Admiral Krell.
I'M UNDER ORDERS TO
ERADICATE THIS COLONY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
MY DOCTOR CAN STOP THE PLAGUE.
I HAVE
A MORE EFFECTIVE SOLUTION.
HELLO, ADMIRAL KRELL.
THIS IS DR. PHLOX.
I AM TRANSMITTING
THE DETAILS OF AN ANTIVIRUS.
FEEL FREE TO HAVE YOUR
PHYSICIANS CONFIRM MY FINDINGS,
AND YOU'RE WELCOME TO CALL
WITH ANY QUESTIONS.
My orders are clear.
CAPTAIN ARCHER,
YOUR SHIPS ARE NOW THE PROPERTY
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
STAND DOWN OR BE DESTROYED.
[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
PROCEED AS PLANNED.
LEAVE NOTHING STANDING.
THE LEAD SHIP'S MOVING
INTO A LOWER ORBIT.
THEY'RE CHARGING WEAPONS.
INTERCEPT COURSE.
-COLUMBIA.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPING ]
I CAN'T GET THROUGH.
THEY'RE FIRING ON THE COLONY.
TARGET THEIR DISRUPTORS.
HOW STRONG ARE THE SHIELDS
AROUND THIS PLACE?
NOT STRONG ENOUGH!
YOU SAID YOU HAD
TWO SHIPS IN ORBIT.
I'M SURE THEY'RE DOING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-ARCHER TO ENTERPRISE.
[ Static ]
THEY'RE CLOSING FROM ASTERN.
AFT CANNONS ARE DOWN.
COLUMBIA TO ENTERPRISE.
LOOKED LIKE YOU
COULD USE A HAND.
[ Static ]
LET'S KEEP THOSE SHIPS
OFF THEIR TAIL.
YOUR SHIPS ARE TAKING DAMAGE.
HOW MUCH LONGER?
AS I SAID, ANOTHER FEW HOURS.
CAN YOU SPEED THAT UP
A LITTLE?
PHLOX, I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
BUT IF WE WANT TO GET OUT
OF HERE IN ONE PIECE,
WE'VE GOT TO GET THAT CURE,
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET IT FAST.
I COULD FINISH THE ANTIVIRUS
IN LESS TIME
IF I HAD A HUMAN HOST TO
REPLICATE ENOUGH ANTIBODIES.
I DON'T SEE
ANY OTHER HUMANS AROUND.
CAPTAIN, I WOULD HAVE
TO EXPOSE YOU TO THE PLAGUE.
I CANNOT PREDICT
WHAT IT MIGHT DO TO YOU.
-WILL IT GIVE YOU THE CURE?
-UNQUESTIONABLY.
LET'S GET STARTED.
WHAT DO YOU INTEND TO DO?
THIS VIRUS MAY BE OUR
BEST WEAPON AGAINST KRELL.
READY WHEN YOU ARE.
ONE OF THE SHIPS
IS LOSING POWER.
THEIR PORT NACELLE
IS VULNERABLE.
THEN FIRE AT WILL.
IN ADDITION TO THE VIRUS,
I'M INJECTING YOU
WITH A METABOLIC CATALYST
TO ACCELERATE
YOUR IMMUNE RESPONSE.
IT WON'T BE PLEASANT.
IT'S NO USE. I CAN'T PENETRATE
THEIR SHIELDS.
COMMANDER, I'VE BROKEN THROUGH
THEIR JAMMING FREQUENCIES.
-[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
-T'POL TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
-[ Static ]
-Captain, respond!
-[ GRUNTING ]
-DR. PHLOX HERE.
THE CAPTAIN IS
INDISPOSED AT THE MOMENT.
I imagine you have
your hands full up there.
TO SAY THE LEAST.
WE HAVE A PLAN
TO DEFUSE THE SITUATION,
BUT WE'LL NEED A FEW MORE
MINUTES TO CARRY IT OUT.
I'D APPRECIATE IT IF YOU
COULD KEEP THE CEILING
FROM CAVING IN ON US
UNTIL THEN.
Understood.
HOW MUCH HULL PLATING
DO WE HAVE LEFT?
62%.
MR. MAYWEATHER,
PUT US DIRECTLY
BETWEEN THAT CRUISER
AND THE COLONY.
YOU MAY WANT TO DIVERT
ALL AVAILABLE POWER
TO OUR DORSAL PLATING.
AYE, AYE.
[ GRUNTING ]
IT'S WORKING.
-THEY'RE SHIFTING THEIR ORBIT.
-STAY WITH THEM.
-HULL PLATING'S DOWN TO 40%.
-KEEP FIRING.
CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ,
PLEASE DIRECT YOUR WEAPONS
AT THE BATTLE CRUISER.
WISH I COULD HELP.
WE JUST LOST OUR WEAPONS.
IT'S DONE. HOLD HIM.
AAH!
WE'VE GOT IT!
IS THE CANISTER READY?
IT'S SET TO DISPERSE
FIVE SECONDS AFTER TRANSPORT.
SEND IT.
OPEN A CHANNEL TO KRELL.
HULL PLATING'S NEARLY DOWN.
WE CAN'T HOLD THIS POSITION
MUCH LONGER.
ADMIRAL KRELL,
DR. PHLOX AGAIN.
BY NOW YOU MAY HAVE NOTICED
the small package
which we sent to your bridge.
What you may not know
is that it contains
a potent sample of
the metagenic virus.
Even as we speak,
it is dispersing
throughout your ship,
infecting you and your crew.
YOU'RE LYING!
Check your internal sensors.
You will find
THAT THE ATMOSPHERE CONTAINS
APPROXIMATELY 20 PARTS PER
MILLION OF THE VIRAL STRAIN.
OR IF YOU DON'T TRUST YOUR
SENSORS, TRUST YOUR SENSES.
YOU WILL FEEL
THE INITIAL SYMPTOMS
IN ABOUT 30 MINUTES --
A TIGHTNESS IN THE CHEST,
IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT,
TINGLING IN
YOUR CRANIAL RIDGES.
THIS IS A COWARDLY ATTACK!
MAYBE SO. BUT I AM PREPARED
TO GIVE YOU THE CURE.
THANKS TO CAPTAIN ARCHER,
I HAVE MANAGED
TO COMPLETE THE ANTIVIRUS.
OF COURSE, IF YOU
DESTROY THIS COLONY, WELL,
TREATING YOU AND YOUR CREW
COULD PROVE DIFFICULT.
I SUGGEST YOU POWER DOWN
YOUR WEAPONS, ADMIRAL,
AND LET ME CURE YOUR PEOPLE.
[ SIGHS ]
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
ADMIRAL KRELL HAS
CONVINCED THE HIGH COUNCIL
TO CALL OFF
THEIR STERILIZATION PROGRAM.
THEY'VE PROMISED TO
DISTRIBUTE PHLOX'S CURE
THROUGHOUT THE EMPIRE.
THERE'S NO TRACE OF THE VIRUS
IN YOUR BLOODSTREAM.
MY TARG WON'T EVEN
RECOGNIZE ME.
IN THE FUTURE,
IT MAY BE POSSIBLE TO REVERSE
THE COSMETIC EFFECTS.
I SUPPOSE
THIS IS WHAT I DESERVE.
MILLIONS OF MY PEOPLE WILL HAVE
TO LIVE WITH THIS DISFIGUREMENT.
IT'LL BE PASSED
ON TO OUR CHILDREN.
LIFE WON'T BE EASY FOR US.
YOU DID YOUR BEST TO
CORRECT YOUR MISTAKES.
THAT'S ALL WE CAN
ASK OF OURSELVES.
I DOUBT MY SUPERIORS WILL ALLOW
ME TO REMAIN IN MY POSITION.
I'LL NEED TO FIND
A NEW SPECIALTY.
PERHAPS CRANIAL
RECONSTRUCTION.
I HAVE A FEELING THAT'S
ABOUT TO BECOME VERY POPULAR.
I'M GRATEFUL FOR EVERYTHING
THAT YOU'VE DONE.
-[ SIGHS ]
-HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
NOT TOO BAD, ASIDE FROM SOME
STRANGE CRAVINGS.
A PLATEFUL OF LIVE GAGH
SOUNDS PRETTY GOOD RIGHT NOW.
THE CRAVINGS SHOULD DISAPPEAR
IN A DAY OR SO,
ALONG WITH YOUR, UH, RIDGES.
NO, I'D KEEP THEM
IF I WERE YOU, CAPTAIN.
IT MAKES YOU LOOK INTIMIDATING.
I SHOULD GET BACK ON THE ROAD.
ONE OF US NEEDS TO GET
SOME EXPLORING DONE.
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU SURVIVED
ALL THESE YEARS WITHOUT ME.
SHOULDN'T YOU BE JOINING HER?
I ASKED TRIP TO STICK
AROUND FOR A LITTLE WHILE
TO HELP US OUT WITH REPAIRS.
INDEED.
OUR NEW CHIEF ENGINEER WILL NO
DOUBT BE DELIGHTED FOR THE HELP.
NO, KELBY'S GOT
NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT.
I'M ONLY HERE TEMPORARILY.
[ COMPUTER BEEPS ]
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I CALLED TO THANK YOU.
EVERYTHING WENT
ACCORDING TO OUR PROJECTIONS.
THE EMPIRE'S BEEN STABILIZED.
I DOUBT VERY MUCH
THEY'LL BE EXPERIMENTING
WITH AUGMENTS ANY TIME SOON.
WE COULD'VE EXPLAINED
EVERYTHING TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
THAT'S NOT HOW KRELL
WANTED THINGS DONE.
SINCE WHEN DO WE DO THINGS
THE WAY THE KLINGONS WANT?
WHEN IT'S IN OUR INTEREST.
I HAD TO KEEP CERTAIN DETAILS
FROM YOU AS WELL.
I HOPE THERE ARE
NO HARD FEELINGS.
THIS MISSION
WOULDN'T HAVE SUCCEEDED
WITHOUT YOU, LIEUTENANT.
DON'T EVER CONTACT ME AGAIN.
IS THAT CLEAR?
MAYBE YOU DIDN'T UNDERSTAND
OUR RECRUITMENT POLICY.
YOU CAN'T SIMPLY WALK AWAY.
I ANSWER TO ONE COMMANDING
OFFICER -- JONATHAN ARCHER.
LIEUTENANT, WHY DON'T WE --