CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
DECEMBER 27, 2154.
WE'RE ON COURSE
FOR THE BERENGARIUS SYSTEM,
A POTENTIAL SITE
FOR THE FIRST IN A SERIES
OF PROPOSED STARBASES.
A VULCAN
SCIENCE VESSEL SURVEYED
THE SEVENTH PLANET
OVER 50 YEARS AGO.
THE FILE STATES
IT'S AN M-CLASS WORLD
WITH A FLOURISHING ECOSYSTEM.
-NO INTELLIGENT LIFE.
-SOUNDS PROMISING.
THEY DID REPORT ONE DISTINCTIVE
FEATURE WHICH BEARS MENTIONING.
AND THAT IS?
A SPECIES OF FLYING REPTILE,
SOME REPORTEDLY
OVER 200 METERS LONG.
THEY'RE ALSO SAID
TO BREATHE FIRE.
THERE'S BEEN LINGERING QUESTIONS
OVER THE ACCURACY
OF THIS REPORT.
CAN'T WAIT TO FIND OUT.
[ BEEPING ]
THERE'S A SHIP.
IT'S ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
I DON'T RECOGNIZE
THE CONFIGURATION.
LET'S SEE IT.
DOESN'T LOOK VERY FRIENDLY.
TACTICAL ALERT.
LET'S SEE WHAT THEY WANT, HOSHI.
[ BEEPING ]
THEY'RE RESPONDING.
CAPTAIN ARCHER.
AND YOU ARE?
HARRAD-SAR.
DEACTIVATE YOUR WEAPON SYSTEMS
IMMEDIATELY
OR I'LL BE FORCED
TO OPEN FIRE.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
YOU'RE STILL TARGETING
MY SHIP.
AND YOU'RE TARGETING MINE.
IT SEEMS WE'RE AT AN IMPASSE.
NOT FOR LONG.
INSTEAD OF SITTING HERE
POINTING GUNS AT EACH OTHER,
WHY DON'T WE DEACTIVATE
OUR WEAPONS TOGETHER?
VERY WELL.
[ CLICKS ]
[ BEEPING ]
NOW, WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU?
I HAVE A PROPOSAL TO MAKE.
I'M LISTENING.
I PREFER TO DISCUSS BUSINESS
IN PERSON.
YOU'RE INVITED ABOARD MY SHIP.
WE'VE DEALT WITH
YOUR PEOPLE BEFORE.
THE EXPERIENCE WASN'T
ONE I CARE TO REPEAT.
IF YOU CAN GIVE ME SOME IDEA
WHAT THIS IS ABOUT...
WHAT I HAVE TO SAY
COULD SMOOTH THE RELATIONS
BETWEEN YOUR STARFLEET
AND THE ORION SYNDICATE.
MY HOSPITALITY IS RENOWNED,
CAPTAIN.
I DON'T OFFER IT TO EVERYONE.
AND ONCE I HAVE BEEN REFUSED,
I NEVER OFFER IT AGAIN.
THE LAST ORIONS WE RAN INTO
ALMOST TURNED NINE OF OUR
CREW MEMBERS INTO SLAVES.
LET'S AT LEAST ASK HIM
TO COME HERE.
I HAVE A FEELING HE'D SEE IT
AS AN INSULT.
I CAN LIVE WITH THAT.
ANY CHANCE TO IMPROVE RELATIONS
WITH THE SYNDICATE,
I'M WILLING TO TAKE THAT RISK.
ANYTHING TO HAVE ONE LESS
HOSTILE SPECIES OUT THERE.
SEVEN OF THE TRANSFER CONDUITS
ARE BACK ONLINE.
THE EIGHTH IS STILL
GIVING US SOME TROUBLE.
DID YOU RUN A PHASE DIAGNOSTIC?
IT CAME BACK NEGATIVE.
BETTER WORK UP A BYPASS.
ALREADY UNDER WAY.
KELBY.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM?
I'M NOT SURE WHAT YOU MEAN, SIR.
LOOK, THE CAPTAIN
ASKED ME TO STICK AROUND.
AS SOON AS THE REPAIRS ARE DONE,
I'M BACK ON COLUMBIA.
AND IT'S NO REFLECTION ON ME
THAT THE CAPTAIN WANTS YOU
TO OVERSEE THE WORK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I WAS HIS CHIEF ENGINEER
FOR FOUR YEARS.
WELL, IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
HE'S READY TO LET YOU GO.
I'D BETTER GET ON IT.
HE THINKS HE'S GONNA
LOSE HIS PROMOTION.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN DO TO HELP?
-WITH KELBY?
-WITH THE ENGINE.
I COULD USE A SECOND PAIR
OF EYES ON THE FIELD MATRIX.
THE PATTERN'S BOTHERING ME,
AND I CAN'T FIGURE OUT WHY.
I'LL TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
THANKS.
COMMANDER,
HAVE YOU BEEN EXPERIENCING
-ANY UNUSUAL DAYDREAMS?
-DAYDREAMS?
ACCOMPANIED BY INTENSE AUDITORY
AND VISUAL SENSATIONS.
THEY WOULD INVOLVE ME.
YOU'RE WONDERING IF I'VE BEEN
HAVING ANY DAYDREAMS ABOUT YOU?
ESSENTIALLY.
WELL, LET ME THINK.
-NO, NOTHING COMES TO MIND.
-FORGET I MENTIONED IT.
HAVE YOU BEEN HAVING DAYDREAMS
ABOUT ME?
IT'S NOT IMPORTANT.
ARE YOU GONNA TELL ME
WHAT THIS IS ABOUT?
NO.
I AM A PRIVATEER.
MY ALLEGIANCE
IS TO MYSELF ALONE.
I EARN MY LIVING IN VARIOUS
WAYS -- BUYING, SELLING.
PLUNDERING?
WHEN THE SITUATION CALLS FOR IT.
PIRACY IS A RISKY BUSINESS.
I PREFER COMMERCE.
THIS IS FROM A PLANET
IN THE GORN HEGEMONY.
THE GORN?
THE LESS SAID ABOUT THEM,
THE BETTER.
HOWEVER, THEY BREW THE FINEST
OF MERIDOR IN THE FIVE SYSTEMS.
DELICIOUS.
OH, I'M PLEASED.
YOU HAVE ACQUIRED SOMETHING
OF A REPUTATION, CAPTAIN.
FAVORABLE, I HOPE.
WELL, YOU'RE WANTED
IN THE KLINGON EMPIRE
AND THE ORION SYNDICATE.
I DON'T KNOW.
I-I WOULD HAVE IMAGINED
SUCH A MAN
WOULD HAVE
A MORE ROBUST APPETITE.
WITH ALL THOSE PEOPLE AFTER ME,
I NEED TO STAY QUICK ON MY FEET.
[ LAUGHS ] YES.
YOU SAID YOU HAD SOMETHING
IMPORTANT TO DISCUSS WITH US.
WELL, IT'S POOR CUSTOM
TO DISCUSS BUSINESS
BEFORE ENTERTAINMENT.
IF THE FOOD DIDN'T
AROUSE YOUR HUNGER...
THIS SHOULD.
[ MID-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ BELLS TINKLING ]
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I CAN'T THINK.
CAPTAIN?
I'D HAVE TO AGREE
WITH MY TACTICAL OFFICER.
I THINK SHE LIKES YOU.
HER NAME IS NAVAAR.
SHE'S THE MOST EXPERIENCED
OF THE THREE.
THEY'RE SISTERS.
I PURCHASED THEM AT
A TRADING POST YOU ONCE VISITED.
INCREDIBLE, AREN'T THEY?
THEY CAN MAKE YOU FORGET
MOST OF YOUR TROUBLES.
OF COURSE,
CREATURES SUCH AS THESE
COME WITH TROUBLES OF THEIR OWN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BUT WOMEN ARE THE SAME
THROUGHOUT THE GALAXY,
AREN'T THEY?
NOW WE CAN TALK BUSINESS.
HE CLAIMS
HE'S DISCOVERED A PLANET
WITH LARGE DEPOSITS
OF MAGNESITE --
ENOUGH TO BUILD
1,000 WARP REACTORS.
AND THAT'S JUST WHAT
HIS SCANNERS COULD DETECT.
HE'S OFFERING
TO GIVE US THE COORDINATES.
WHY WOULD HE
DIVULGE HIS INFORMATION?
HE DOESN'T HAVE
THE INFRASTRUCTURE
TO GET THE MAGNESITE
OUT OF THE GROUND.
SO HE WANTS STARFLEET
TO CONSTRUCT MINING FACILITIES.
AND HE'LL GET A 10% SHARE.
HE'S ALSO PROMISED
TO HELP ESTABLISH A DIALOGUE
BETWEEN STARFLEET
AND THE ORION SYNDICATE.
ARE YOU GOING TO
ACCEPT HIS OFFER?
I ALREADY HAVE.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE HERE
SEEKING MY ADVICE.
HARRAD-SAR INSISTED
THAT I ACCEPT A GIFT
TO CELEBRATE THE TRANSACTION.
GIVEN THE SITUATION,
I, UH, COULDN'T REFUSE.
UH, WE'RE ON "D" DECK NOW,
WHERE MOST OF THE CREW QUARTERS
ARE LOCATED.
WHERE DOES CAPTAIN ARCHER STAY?
ON "E". THAT'S, UH,
ONE DECK BELOW US.
HOW MANY LEVELS ARE THERE?
UM, A TOTAL OF SEVEN.
SEVEN DECKS.
WE'VE ARRANGED THESE FOR YOU.
YOU NEED SOMETHING TO DO?
UH, THE OTHER TWO ROOMS
ARE RIGHT NEXT DOOR.
I'LL SHOW YOU IN A MOMENT.
CAPTAIN ARCHER
HAS A VERY LARGE SHIP.
IT'S ROOMY.
BUT EVERYTHING'S SO FUNCTIONAL.
THERE'S NO COLOR.
I HADN'T REALLY THOUGHT
ABOUT IT, TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
AT LEAST IT'S PRIVATE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
LIEUTENANT REED.
UH, MALCOLM.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU,
LIEUTENANT REED MALCOLM.
MALCOLM'S FINE.
WELL, UM, SOMEONE
WILL BE BY SHORTLY
TO SHOW YOU
HOW EVERYTHING WORKS.
IN THE MEANTIME, JUST TRY
TO MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME.
RIGHT.
UH, THIS WAY, LADIES.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
HARRAD-SAR HAS TURNED OVER
THE COORDINATES
OF THE PLANET HE DESCRIBED.
WE'RE EN ROUTE
TO VERIFY HIS CLAIMS.
I'VE BEEN HEARING
SOME CONCERNS FROM THE CREW.
-CONCERNS?
-THE ORION WOMEN.
THEIR PRESENCE
IS BECOMING DISRUPTIVE.
YOU'RE TELLING ME.
THE CREW ISN'T USED TO
HAVING ORIONS ONBOARD.
IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
OUR GUESTS VISITED
THE MESS HALL THIS MORNING.
AS A RESULT, 12 CREWMEN REPORTED
LATE FOR THEIR SHIFTS.
I GET THE PICTURE.
IT'S PRIMARILY THEIR ATTIRE.
OR LACK OF IT.
I'LL SEE ABOUT
ASSIGNING THEM SOME CLOTHES.
IT MIGHT ALSO BE A GOOD IDEA
IF YOU HAVE A WORD WITH THEM.
THEY'RE STILL UNDER THE
IMPRESSION THEY BELONG TO YOU.
UNLESS A NEW POLICY
HAS BEEN INSTATED,
I BELIEVE STARFLEET
DOESN'T CONDONE SLAVERY.
I'LL SPEAK TO THEM
FIRST CHANCE I GET.
THANK YOU.
[ GRUNTING ]
LIEUTENANT.
[ BEEPING ]
HAVE YOU SEEN THEM YET?
I RAN INTO ONE OF THEM
IN THE CORRIDOR.
[chuckling]
THEY'RE REALLY...
YEAH, I KNOW.
[ PANTING ]
I KNOW.
[ GRUNTING ]
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO DO?
GET THEM OUT OF MY HEAD!
THE PAIN HELPS.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT.
YEAH, OKAY.
WHEN I WAS ON MY PARENTS' SHIP,
WE PICKED UP SOME DELTANS ONCE.
THEIR SHIP WAS
HAVING ENGINE TROUBLE.
I DON'T KNOW THAT SPECIES.
THE FEMALES ARE
UNBELIEVABLY ATTRACTIVE.
VERY OPEN ABOUT...
[ GRUNTING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
I WAS 15.
I COULDN'T THINK STRAIGHT.
I COULD BARELY BREATHE.
ONLY THING
THAT GOT ME THROUGH IT
WAS WEIGHT-TRAINING WITH MY DAD.
HE SAID IF I WAS EXHAUSTED,
IDLE HANDS AND ALL THAT.
WELL, DID IT HELP?
HELPED MY BICEPS.
I'D GO HEAVIER.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ PEOPLE MURMURING ]
-WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
-I WANTED TO THANK YOU.
YOU WERE VERY KIND THIS MORNING,
HELPING ME FIND THE MESS HALL.
IT WAS NO PROBLEM.
LOOK, I, UH...
WOW. IS THAT THE ENGINE?
IT'S THE WARP REACTOR.
YOU CAN FEEL THE POWER.
YOU PROMISED YOU'D
SHOW ME ENGINEERING.
I KNOW.
HARRAD-SAR NEVER LET US
LEAVE OUR ROOMS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE THIS PLACE.
I COULD SHOW YOU AROUND.
IF IT WON'T GET YOU
INTO TROUBLE.
COME ON.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT
FOR A HEADACHE?
THAT DEPENDS ON
WHAT'S CAUSING IT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN EXPERIENCING THIS?
A FEW HOURS.
WHAT IS IT?
ENSIGN KEELY WAS HERE WITH
A HEADACHE SEVERAL MINUTES AGO.
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?
PERFECTLY.
JUST AS YOU ARE.
IT'S PROBABLY JUST STRESS.
PLENTY OF THAT GOING AROUND.
OR IT COULD BE
OUR NEW PASSENGERS.
THE ORION FEMALES?
WHY SHOULD THEY
GIVE YOU A HEADACHE?
I'M JUST NOT USED TO SEEING GUYS
TRIP OVER THEMSELVES LIKE THAT.
JUST A LITTLE
HEALTHY SEXUAL ENERGY.
HELPS KEEP THE BLOOD PUMPING.
IF YOU ASK ME, IT'S PUMPING
A LITTLE TOO HARD.
-I'M SURPRISED AT YOU, ENSIGN.
-WHY?
YOU NEVER STRUCK ME
AS BEING PRONE TO JEALOUSY.
THIS.
THIS SHOULD DO VERY NICELY.
[ BEEPING ]
-PHLOX!
-[ GRUNTS ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WELL, I MUST BE
NEARING A SLEEP CYCLE.
I THOUGHT YOU JUST HAD ONE.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DID -- A WEEK AGO.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S A GOOD BET
THE PROBLEM'S RIGHT THERE.
TAKE IT APART.
[ LAUGHING ]
THE INJECTORS FEED
INTO THE DILITHIUM CHAMBER.
THAT'S WHERE
THE MATTER AND ANTIMATTER MIX.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE CRYSTALS LET YOU
CONTROL THE REACTION.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LIEUTENANT.
TALK TO YOU A SECOND?
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
[ SIGHS ]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
SIR?
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
RECALIBRATING THE E.P.S. TAPS,
-NOT GIVING A TOUR.
-SHE'S ONLY BEEN HERE
A COUPLE OF MINUTES.
NOT TO MENTION THE FACT THAT
SHE DOESN'T HAVE CLEARANCE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
CHECKED WITH ME FIRST.
WELL, I GUESS
I CAN'T DO ANYTHING RIGHT.
JUST ASK HER TO LEAVE.
NO, SIR.
I'M NOT THROUGH TALKING TO HER.
-THAT WAS AN ORDER.
-AND I'M REFUSING.
WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
YOU'VE BEEN ON MY CASE
SINCE THE SECOND YOU GOT BACK.
THAT'S WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH ME.
AND I'M TELLING YOU,
IT STOPS HERE.
KELBY,
YOU'RE WALKING A FINE LINE.
SO ARE YOU, COMMANDER.
YOU'RE CONFINED TO QUARTERS.
AND WHAT IF I DON'T WANT TO GO?
IT'S EITHER YOUR QUARTERS
OR THE BRIG.
GET OUT OF HERE NOW.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
I WAS WONDERING WHEN YOU
WERE GOING TO COME SEE ME.
AFTER ALL, I'VE BEEN
YOUR PROPERTY FOR TWO DAYS.
NAVAAR, YOU AND YOUR SISTERS
DON'T BELONG TO ME
OR ANYONE ELSE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ON MY WORLD, SLAVERY'S BEEN
ILLEGAL FOR HUNDREDS OF YEARS.
ARE YOU SAYING
THAT YOU DON'T WANT US?
I'M SAYING THAT YOU'RE HERE
AS OUR GUESTS,
NOT OUR PROPERTY.
I'VE BEEN A SLAVE
MY ENTIRE LIFE...
ON DIFFERENT WORLDS,
FOR DIFFERENT OWNERS.
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN TO ME?
YOU'RE FREE
TO START A NEW LIFE.
IN THE MEANTIME, I'VE ASKED
MY PROTOCOL OFFICER, HOSHI SATO,
TO BRIEF YOU
ON SHIP'S OPERATIONS.
THERE ARE CERTAIN AREAS
THAT ARE RESERVED
FOR STARFLEET PERSONNEL.
I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
IN ENGINEERING.
I'VE ALREADY SPOKEN TO D'NESH.
I'M SORRY.
THERE'S NO REASON
TO APOLOGIZE.
IT'S A BIG ADJUSTMENT
FOR THE THREE OF YOU.
MAY I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
DO YOU FIND ME ATTRACTIVE?
I'D BE LYING IF I SAID NO.
I'VE KNOWN SO FEW HONEST MEN.
AND EVEN THOUGH
YOU DON'T WISH TO OWN ME,
I STILL WISH TO PLEASE YOU.
IF I CHOOSE TO DO THIS...
...WOULD THAT VIOLATE
YOUR SHIP'S PROTOCOL?
NOT NECESSARILY.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
-[ BEEP ]
-ARCHER HERE.
We're coming up on the planet.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
I RECOMMEND WE GO
TO TACTICAL ALERT, SIR.
WE CAN'T BE CERTAIN
THIS ISN'T SOME KIND OF A TRAP.
GO AHEAD.
WE'RE ALREADY PICKING UP
LARGE DEPOSITS OF MAGNESITE.
HARRAD-SAR
WAS TELLING THE TRUTH?
-IT WOULD SEEM SO.
-KEEP SCANNING.
I WANT TO KNOW
HOW MUCH IS DOWN THERE.
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
[ BEEPING ]
A POWER READING.
NOT ON THE SURFACE,
IN THE UPPER ATMOSPHERE.
A SHIP?
UNCERTAIN.
TRY HAILING THEM.
THE CLOUD LAYER
IS HIGHLY IONIZED.
IT'S OBSCURING OUR SCANNERS.
GET US CLOSER,
WITHIN 10 KILOMETERS.
THEY'RE NOT RESPONDING.
-[ BEEPING ]
-THERE IT IS.
IT'S AN UNKNOWN CONFIGURATION.
THEY'RE LOCKING WEAPONS.
[ BEEPING ]
EXTREMELY LOW YIELD.
BARELY SCRATCHED US.
IT'S EQUIPPED
WITH NUMEROUS SENSORS,
MOST LIKELY A SCIENCE VESSEL.
ITS PRESENCE HERE
COULD SIMPLY BE A COINCIDENCE.
THEY'RE FIRING AGAIN.
NO DAMAGE.
THEY COULD SHOOT AT US ALL DAY.
PHASE CANNONS.
SIR?
A PHASE-CANNON HIT
WILL DESTROY THEM.
WHICH MEANS THEY WON'T
BE SHOOTING AT US ANYMORE.
IF WE SIMPLY WITHDRAW,
THEY'LL MOST LIKELY CEASE
THEIR ATTACK AND MOVE ON.
AND MAYBE THEY WON'T.
TARGET THEM.
LIEUTENANT.
CAPTAIN.
LOCK PHASE CANNONS!
NO.
SIR...
THEY'RE MOVING OFF.
I HAVE JUST AS MUCH EXPERIENCE.
I'M SMARTER, YOUNGER.
YOU'RE BETTER THAN HIM.
WE'RE THE ONLY ONES
WHO THINK THAT.
TUCKER'S GOING TO
TAKE BACK HIS POSITION?
HE DENIES IT, BUT I KNOW
HE'S PLANNING ON STAYING.
IT DOESN'T SEEM FAIR.
IT ISN'T.
LET'S NOT TALK ABOUT IT ANYMORE.
WHAT?
I'M USED TO BEING WITH MEN
WHO TAKE WHAT THEY WANT.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU CAN'T LET HIM
TREAT YOU LIKE THIS.
HE'S MY SUPERIOR OFFICER.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE DIFFERENT.
STAY. WAIT.
DON'T LEAVE.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO
TO KEEP ME FOREVER?
FOREVER?
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
ANYTHING.
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
[ BEEPING ]
[ CLANKING ]
[ WHIRRING ]
KELBY!
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
UGH!
BLOW THE DAMPENERS!
MOVE!
HE BLEW OUT EVERY JUNCTION
IN THE E.P.S. SYSTEM.
IF WE HADN'T GOTTEN
TO HIM, WE MIGHT NOT HAVE
A SHIP UNDER OUR FEET.
-WHEN CAN WE GET UNDER WAY?
-I'M NOT SURE WE CAN
GET UNDER WAY.
HE DID A PRETTY THOROUGH JOB.
-KELBY.
-I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING!
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
WHATEVER HE TOLD YOU,
IT'S A LIE!
THREE OTHER PEOPLE WERE THERE.
THEY ALL SAW YOU.
TELL ME WHY YOU DID THIS.
HE'S TRYING TO GET RID OF ME.
DON'T LISTEN TO HIM!
CAPTAIN, HIS ADRENALINE LEVELS
ARE DANGEROUSLY HIGH.
I NEED TO ADMINISTER
A SEDATIVE.
NOT TILL I GET
SOME ANSWERS FIRST.
IN HIS CURRENT STATE, HE CAN'T
GIVE YOU COHERENT ANSWERS.
I JUST WANT TO GO BACK
TO ENGINEERING.
TO ENGINEERING!
-BE QUIET!
-WHAT'S WRONG WITH HIM?
IT'S THE SAME THING THAT'S
AFFECTING EVERYONE ON THIS SHIP.
IT'S A HIGHLY POTENT
PHEROMONE.
WHEN EXPOSED TO HUMAN MALES,
IT ACCELERATES THE METABOLISM,
CAUSING AGGRESSION AND
ULTIMATELY A FORM OF DELUSION.
THE ORIONS?
HMM. WOMEN ABOARD THE SHIP
HAVE ALSO BEEN AFFECTED.
I'VE RECEIVED AN INCREASING
NUMBER OF COMPLAINTS
ABOUT HEADACHES
AND LISTLESSNESS.
I SUSPECT THE PHEROMONE
ACTS AS A DEFENSE MECHANISM
AGAINST COMPETITION.
HMM.
YOU OKAY?
[ INHALES ]
MM.
IT'S IMPACTED MY SLEEP CYCLE.
I'M HAVING TO RELY ON, UH,
STIMULANTS TO STAY AWAKE.
DOESN'T SEEM TO
BE AFFECTING YOU.
I'VE SCANNED A GOOD NUMBER
OF THE CREW.
SO FAR, THE ONLY PEOPLE WHO
HAVEN'T BEEN AFFECTED ARE T'POL
AND COMMANDER TUCKER.
WHY ME?
I WOULD HAVE TO RUN
SOME MORE TESTS.
BUT FOR THE REST OF US, THE
EFFECT SEEMS TO BE CUMULATIVE.
THE LONGER WE'RE EXPOSED, THE
MORE PRONOUNCED THE RESULTS ARE.
SO THIS IS WHAT YOU MEANT
WHEN YOU SAID WE WERE FREE
TO START NEW LIVES?
WE FOUND THIS IN YOUR QUARTERS.
HMM, IT SEEMS WE HAVE
NO PRIVACY, EITHER.
IT'S A COMMUNICATION DEVICE.
YOU'VE BEEN IN CONTACT
WITH HARRAD-SAR
AS RECENTLY AS TWO HOURS AGO.
AND IF I HAVE?
YOU WERE SENT HERE
TO DISABLE MY SHIP.
THAT WAS HIS PLAN
FROM THE START, WASN'T IT?
HARRAD-SAR CONTACTED ME TO SEE
IF WE'D BEEN TREATED WELL.
DR. PHLOX BELIEVES
THAT PROLONGED EXPOSURE
TO YOUR PHEROMONES
MAKES MEN DELUSIONAL
AND EXTREMELY VULNERABLE
TO SUGGESTION.
THAT'S HOW YOU CONVINCED KELBY
TO SABOTAGE OUR ENGINES.
YOUR CREWMAN ACTED ALONE.
I HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
IT SEEMS THE ONLY DELUSION HERE
IS YOUR OWN.
DAMN IT! IT'S TIME TO START
TELLING ME THE TRUTH!
I'M WORRIED ABOUT YOU, CAPTAIN.
YOU DON'T SEEM WELL.
I'M NOT THE ONE
YOU SHOULD BE WORRIED ABOUT.
I CAN SEE YOU'RE NOT VERY
EXPERIENCED AT MAKING THREATS.
I'M A LOT BETTER
AT CARRYING THEM OUT.
WE WERE A GIFT, NOTHING MORE.
A TRUE COMMANDER WOULD KNOW HOW
TO APPRECIATE SUCH A GESTURE.
TELL ME.
WHEN'S HE GOING TO ATTACK US?
NO ONE IS COMING
TO ATTACK YOUR SHIP.
PLEASE, RELEASE US.
CAPTAIN.
I'M OBVIOUSLY NOT THE ONLY WOMAN
WITH POWER OVER YOU.
GET DOWN TO ENGINEERING.
DO WHAT YOU CAN TO HELP TRIP.
IT'S BETTER IF I STAY
ON THE BRIDGE.
I DON'T NEED YOU
TO LOOK AFTER ME.
YOU'RE NOT IMMUNE
TO THESE PHEROMONES.
-YOUR JUDGMENT IS IMPAIRED.
-I CAN HANDLE IT.
WE NEED TO GET THE ENGINES
BACK ONLINE.
I DON'T WANT TO BE A SITTING
DUCK WHEN HARRAD-SAR GETS HERE.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
THE CAPTAIN ASKED ME
TO OFFER MY ASSISTANCE.
GREAT.
YOU CAN RUN THROUGH
THESE DIAGNOSTICS.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND ANYTHING
THAT ISN'T FRIED.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THEY'RE COMIN' AFTER US?
IT'S LIKELY.
THE TRANSMISSION SENT
BY THE ORION FEMALES
SUGGEST THAT HARRAD-SAR'S SHIP
IS GETTING CLOSER.
YOU KNOW, I KEEP THINKING BACK
TO OUR FIRST MISSION
WHEN WE MET THE SULIBAN.
I WAS SO DAMN NAIVE.
I ACTUALLY THOUGHT IT
WAS THE LAST TIME WE'D
HAVE TO FIGHT SOMEONE.
-I SAID LEAVE IT ALONE!
-GET YOUR HANDS OFF OF ME!
KNOCK IT OFF!
THAT'S AN ORDER!
START UP AGAIN, YOU'LL BOTH
END UP IN THE BRIG! UNDERSTAND?
NOW GO HELP MASARO
WITH THE INJECTORS.
NOW!
GET BACK TO WORK.
THAT'S THE THIRD ONE
IN THE LAST HOUR.
THERE HAVE BEEN ALTERCATIONS
THROUGHOUT THE SHIP.
THE CAPTAIN'S BEEN AFFECTED.
I'M CONCERNED ABOUT HIM.
THE THING I CAN'T FIGURE OUT
IS WHY I'M IMMUNE.
THAT MIGHT HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO WITH ME.
YOU?
THERE'S A LONG-HELD BELIEF
THAT WHEN A VULCAN MATES,
THERE'S A SHARED PSYCHIC BOND.
WE DIDN'T MATE.
UH-HUH.
OKAY, WHAT DO YOU MEAN
BY PSYCHIC BOND?
IT'S DIFFICULT TO EXPLAIN.
FEELINGS, THOUGHTS,
EVEN IMAGES CAN BE SHARED.
THOSE DAYDREAMS.
WHAT?
[ SIGHS ]
WHEN I SAID BEFORE THAT I WASN'T
HAVING ANY DAYDREAMS ABOUT YOU,
IT WASN'T ACTUALLY TRUE.
SO IF WE'RE BONDED,
WHAT DOES THIS HAVE TO DO
WITH ME NOT BEING AFFECTED
BY THE ORIONS?
I'M IMMUNE TO THE PHEROMONES
BECAUSE OF MY VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY.
AND YOU'RE MAKING ME IMMUNE?
APPARENTLY.
OH.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER TO BE
RELIEVED OR...REALLY WORRIED.
[ BEEPING ]
TACTICAL ALERT.
DISTANCE.
400 KILOMETERS.
[ BEEPING ]
HE'S HAILING US.
PUT HIM UP.
CAN I BE OF HELP, CAPTAIN?
DO YOU NEED A TOW?
WE STILL HAVE WEAPONS.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET THIS SHIP
WITHOUT ONE HELL OF A FIGHT.
I'D RATHER
I DIDN'T HAVE TO KILL YOU,
BUT IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES.
THE SYNDICATE WANTS
YOUR HEAD, CAPTAIN.
AND THEY DON'T REALLY CARE
WHETHER OR NOT
IT'S ATTACHED TO YOUR BODY.
HE'S TRYING TO KNOCK OUT
OUR WEAPONS!
THEN TAKE OUT HIS.
FORWARD PHASE CANNONS
ARE DOWN.
PROTECT OUR AFT CANNONS.
HE'S MOVING TOO FAST.
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER TO ENGINEERING.
TRIP!
Can we get more power
to the thrusters?
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO!
WE JUST LOST AFT CANNONS.
TRY TO DIVERT SOME OF THE POWER
FROM THE GRAV PLATING.
WE'RE GOING TO BE
A LITTLE LIGHTER ON OUR FEET!
WHAT THE HELL. I'VE BEEN MEANING
TO LOSE A FEW POUNDS.
REDUCING GRAVITY PLATING TO 90%.
THRUSTERS ARE BACK TO FULL.
HARD TO STARBOARD.
WE'RE STILL TOO SLOW!
TORPEDOES!
THAT LAST HIT
JUST TOOK THEM OUT.
[ BEEPING ]
HE'S POWERING DOWN
HIS WEAPONS.
HE'S COMING ABOUT.
THRUSTERS. FULL ASTERN!
IT'S NOT ENOUGH!
HE'S HAILING.
RELAX, CAPTAIN.
ENJOY THE RIDE.
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
I'M AFRAID
YOU HAVE AN APPOINTMENT
WITH A PAIR OF ORION MARAUDERS.
I DON'T INTEND
TO KEEP THEM WAITING.
RELEASE MY SHIP!
I CAN SEE YOU'RE UPSET,
AND I SYMPATHIZE,
BUT IT'S TRULY OUT OF MY HANDS.
WE'RE BOTH SLAVES
TO THE SITUATION.
THEY CONTROL YOU?
YOU FINALLY REALIZE THAT.
YES, CAPTAIN,
YOU'VE BEEN OPERATING
UNDER A MISCONCEPTION.
IT IS THE MEN WHO ARE
THE SLAVES, NOT THE WOMEN.
[ BEEPING ]
YOU SEE WHAT I'M SEEING?
HIS GRAPPLER'S DIRECTLY ABOVE
OUR MAIN DEFLECTOR READER.
GET UP TO THE BRIDGE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
[ BEEPING ]
THE DEFLECTOR?
WE CAN USE IT TO SEND A POSITRON
BURST THROUGH THE TOWING CABLE.
IF WE'RE LUCKY, IT'LL TRIGGER
AN ENERGY CASCADE.
AND DISABLE HIS POWER SYSTEMS.
DO IT.
T'POL TO ENGINEERING.
I'VE ALMOST GOT IT.
YOU'LL HAVE TO REROUTE
THE MAIN E.P.S. CONDUIT.
UNDERSTOOD.
CAPTAIN.
DECON CHAMBER, COME IN.
THERE'S NO ONE THERE.
WHAT DID YOU DO TO MY MEN?
WE ASKED THEM TO LEAVE
AFTER THEY RELEASED US.
THEY WERE VERY ACCOMMODATING.
GET OFF MY BRIDGE.
IS THAT WHAT YOU REALLY WANT?
BECAUSE IF IT IS,
I'LL GLADLY DO AS YOU SAY.
I ONLY WANT TO MAKE YOU HAPPY.
I DIDN'T THINK
YOU WANTED ME TO GO.
CAPTAIN.
SHE'S JEALOUS.
SHE'LL TRY ANYTHING
TO KEEP US APART.
SHE'LL EVEN DESTROY YOUR SHIP.
HER PRESENCE IS AFFECTING
YOUR JUDGMENT.
ARREST HER.
-DON'T LISTEN!
-DO IT.
-CAPTAIN!
-LIEUTENANT REED.
YES?
TAKE T'POL TO THE BRIG.
YOU HEARD YOUR CAPTAIN.
-AYE, SIR.
-[ GROANS ]
STOP HIM.
WE'RE READY.
[ WHIRRING ]
HIS ENGINES ARE DOWN.
WEAPONS, AS WELL. IT WORKED.
COMMANDER TUCKER...
I'M IMPRESSED.
I'M BEGINNING TO SEE WHO'S
THE TRUE MASTER OF THIS VESSEL.
OH, SAVE IT.
CAPTAIN ARCHER RUNS THIS SHIP.
YOU'RE SWEET-TALKING
THE WRONG GUY.
LET'S GO.
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE ORION WOMEN HAVE BEEN
RETURNED TO HARRAD-SAR,
WHO'S HEADED HOME
AT VERY LOW IMPULSE.
[ ZAPPING ]
-OKAY.
-WHOA.
THE DIZZINESS SHOULD FADE
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
GLAD TO HEAR THAT.
AT LEAST THE PHEROMONES
ARE WEARING OFF.
I HAVEN'T THOUGHT ABOUT
THE ORIONS FOR WHAT,
A WHOLE 10 MINUTES.
THE ENTIRE CREW'S
BEEN BUMPING INTO WALLS.
IT'S LIKE SOMEONE SPIKED
THE WATER SUPPLY.
THE AFTER-EFFECTS WILL BE AROUND
FOR AT LEAST A FEW DAYS.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
YOU'LL BE GLAD TO KNOW
MY LOG WON'T MENTION
YOUR FIRING ON
A FELLOW OFFICER.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
A COURT-MARTIAL WOULD HARDLY
BE A FITTING ENDING
TO THIS INCIDENT.
AT LEAST WE'VE LEARNED
SOMETHING ABOUT THE ORIONS.
YEAH, THE WOMEN ARE IN CHARGE.
IT PROVES THAT EVEN
THE MOST DISAGREEABLE SPECIES
HAVE SOME POSITIVE ATTRIBUTES.
WAS THAT MY IMAGINATION?
I DON'T THINK SO.
IT ALMOST SOUNDED LIKE
YOU WERE MAKING A JOKE.
AT LEAST TRYING TO MAKE ONE.
I ASSURE YOU, IF I EVER
DECIDE TO MAKE A JOKE,
YOU'LL KNOW ABOUT IT.
THERE IT IS AGAIN.
T'POL, IF
I DIDN'T KNOW BETTER,
I'D THINK YOU WERE PICKING UP
SOME OF TRIP'S BAD HABITS.
I GUESS WE PROVED IT AGAIN.
PROVED WHAT?
THAT YOU AND I
MAKE A HELL OF A TEAM.
WE DO SEEM
TO WORK WELL TOGETHER.
EVEN MORE NOW THAT WE'RE
IN EACH OTHER'S HEADS.
YOU'RE RETURNING TO COLUMBIA?
I IMAGINE CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ
IS GETTING PRETTY ANTSY
TO HAVE HER CHIEF ENGINEER BACK.
THERE ARE STILL NUMEROUS REPAIRS
TO BE CARRIED OUT HERE.
I THINK KELBY CAN HANDLE THEM.
HE'D BEEN OBSERVING MY WORK
PRETTY CAREFULLY
WHEN HE WASN'T TRYING
TO BLOW UP THE SHIP.
KELBY IS A FINE ENGINEER,
BUT HE LACKS EXPERIENCE.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST SAY IT?
SAY WHAT?
THAT YOU WANT ME TO COME BACK.
I BELIEVE I DID.
I THINK YOUR PRESENCE HERE
WOULD BE EXTREMELY BENEFICIAL
TO OUR OPERATIONS.
NO.
THAT YOU WANT ME BACK.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
MY MISTAKE.
SEE YOU AROUND.
WAIT. TRIP.
I WANT YOU TO COME BACK.
THEN I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
TRIP!
THREE DAYS AGO,
I TOLD CAPTAIN HERNANDEZ
I WANTED A TRANSFER
BACK TO ENTERPRISE.
THREE DAYS AGO?
I REALIZED THIS IS
WHERE I WAS MEANT TO BE
AND THAT, UH,
THIS THING BETWEEN US
ISN'T THAT BIG OF A DEAL.
AGREED.
GUESS WE GOT
A LOT OF WORK TO DO.