[ RUMBLING ]
[ WIND WHIPPING ]
[ WHOOSHES ]
LIVE LONG AND PROSPER.
[ GUNSHOT ]
BOARD HIS SHIP!
TAKE EVERYTHING YOU CAN!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
JANUARY 13, 2155.
WE'VE LEFT GORLAN STATION
AND HAVE SET A COURSE
TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH OUR ASSAULT FLEET.
MAJOR REED AND THE DOCTOR
HAVE ASKED FOR A FEW MINUTES
TO SHOW ME THEIR LATEST PROJECT.
[ SCREAMING ]
THE BOOTH WILL BE
FAR MORE EFFECTIVE
THAN OUR PREVIOUS
DISCIPLINARY METHODS.
IT CAN STIMULATE THE PAIN CENTER
OF VIRTUALLY ANY HUMANOID.
A SYNAPTIC SCAN CALIBRATES IT
FOR EACH SPECIES.
THEY CALL THIS PROGRESS.
THERE'S SOMETHING TO BE SAID
FOR A GOOD
OLD-FASHIONED FLOGGING.
WELL, THAT'S WHAT'S SO
EXCEPTIONAL ABOUT THIS DEVICE.
TRADITIONAL FORMS OF PUNISHMENT
CAN OVERWHELM
THE NERVOUS SYSTEM.
AFTER A TIME, THE BRAIN CEASES
TO FEEL ANYTHING.
THESE SENSORS CONTINUALLY SHIFT
THE STIMULATION
FROM ONE NERVE CLUSTER
TO ANOTHER,
KEEPING THE SUBJECT
IN A CONSTANT STATE OF AGONY.
[ GROANING ]
I THINK YOU ENJOY YOUR WORK
TOO MUCH, DOCTOR.
WHAT EXACTLY DID MR. TEREV DO?
I'M NOT CERTAIN.
I SUSPECT HE WAS LATE
FOR HIS DUTY SHIFT.
AREN'T ALL TELLARITES
GUILTY OF SOMETHING?
[ TEREV GROANING ]
DID YOU GET A CHANCE
TO LOOK OVER MY PROPOSAL?
-I READ IT.
-AND?
WE'RE GOING TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE FLEET AS ORDERED.
I'M NOT GOING
INTO THOLIAN SPACE
BASED ON DATA
FROM SOME ANONYMOUS SOURCE.
MAYBE YOU HAVEN'T HEARD -- WE
HAVE A REBELLION TO PUT DOWN.
-THE THOLIANS AREN'T
PART OF IT.
-YOU SAW THE DATA.
THIS TECHNOLOGY WOULD GIVE US
A TACTICAL ADVANTAGE.
WE COULD END THE WAR TOMORROW.
YOU SEE THIS AS YOUR BIG CHANCE,
DON'T YOU?
SIR?
YOU BRING THAT SHIP HOME,
AND YOU'LL BE A HERO.
THE EMPEROR PINS
A MEDAL ON YOUR CHEST.
YOU MIGHT EVEN GET THAT COMMAND
YOU'VE ALWAYS WANTED.
MY ONLY CONCERN
IS SAVING THE EMPIRE.
RESUME YOUR STATION.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE MAKING A MISTAKE.
YOU CAN EITHER
GO BACK TO THE BRIDGE,
OR TAKE THE PLACE
OF THAT TELLARITE.
WHICH DO YOU PREFER?
UNDERSTOOD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
REVIEWING STATUS REPORTS.
THIS IS SUPPOSED TO BE
YOUR SANCTUARY...
A PLACE TO GET AWAY
FROM STATUS REPORTS.
[ BEEPS ]
MM.
YOU'RE THE ONE PERSON
ON THIS SHIP
THAT I DON'T MIND GIVING IN TO.
AND PROBABLY THE ONLY ONE
THAT DOESN'T WANT TO SLIP
A KNIFE IN YOUR BACK.
I HEARD THE BATTLE
WENT WELL AT TAU CETI.
-IS THAT WHAT YOU HEARD?
-HMM.
WORD ON THE SHIP IS THAT THE WAR
MAY BE OVER SOON.
I'LL GO BACK TO BRAZIL,
START TEACHING AGAIN.
YOU'LL ACCEPT A COMFORTABLE
DESK JOB AT HEADQUARTERS.
WE'LL HAVE THE WEEKENDS.
[ SIGHS ]
YOU'VE BEEN
LISTENING TO PROPAGANDA.
THINGS WENT BADLY AT TAU CETI.
VERY BADLY.
WE LOST 12 SHIPS.
KEEP THIS TO YOURSELF.
IF THE CREW LEARNS
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED --
FORGET ABOUT THE WAR.
THIS IS OUR TIME.
[ GROANS ]
DON'T!
YOU'LL HANG FOR THIS.
-LOCK HIM IN THE BRIG.
-SIR.
LET ME TAKE HIM
DOWN TO THE CARGO BAY.
I'LL FINISH HIM QUICKLY,
QUIETLY.
I WANT HIM ALIVE.
STILL, IT'D BE TRAGIC
IF THERE WAS AN ACCIDENT
ON THE WAY TO THE BRIG.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS TO FORREST,
I'LL SHOOT YOU MYSELF.
ARE WE CLEAR, MAJOR?
PERFECTLY, SIR.
STAND ASIDE, COMMANDER.
WHERE'S CAPTAIN FORREST?
CONTACT SECURITY.
[ GROANS ]
[ BEEPS ]
THIS IS FIRST OFFICER ARCHER.
IN ACCORDANCE WITH STARFLEET
ORDERS THIS DATE,
I've relieved
Captain Forrest of duty
and assumed
command of Enterprise.
My orders are to take the ship
into Tholian space
for a mission of vital
importance to the Empire.
I can't reveal
the details of our assignment,
but I can tell you this --
If we're successful,
Starfleet will crush
the rebellion once and for all.
NO CREW IN STARFLEET HAS BEEN
TESTED MORE IN BATTLE.
I KNOW I CAN COUNT
ON EACH OF YOU
TO PERFORM YOUR DUTY
TO THE BEST OF YOUR ABILITY.
NOTHING WILL IMPEDE
OUR MARCH TOWARD VICTORY.
LONG LIVE THE EMPIRE.
-LONG LIVE THE EMPIRE!
WE'VE RECEIVED
NO SUCH COMMUNIQUéS
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND.
IT WAS SENT
ON A PRIVATE CHANNEL.
I'D LIKE TO SEE THOSE ORDERS.
ALL IN GOOD TIME.
ALTER OUR HEADING.
2-1-5 MARK 13.
MAXIMUM WARP.
YES, CAPTAIN.
CORPORAL.
ESCORT COMMANDER T'POL
TO CARGO BAY 2.
YOU'LL FIND A SULIBAN
CLOAKING DEVICE THERE.
BRING IT TO ENGINEERING
AND HELP TUCKER INSTALL IT.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED THE CLOAK
TO COMPLETE THIS MISSION.
ENTERPRISE STARLOG,
CAPTAIN JONATHAN ARCHER.
THE CREW HAS ACCEPTED
THE CHANGE OF COMMAND
WITHOUT INCIDENT.
CHIEF ENGINEER TUCKER REPORTS
WE'LL HAVE CLOAKING CAPABILITY
WITHIN 6 HOURS.
THESE ORDERS
APPEAR TO BE AUTHENTIC.
APPEAR?
ALL I REQUIRE FROM YOU
IS YOUR LOYALTY.
DO I HAVE IT?
YOU ARE IN COMMAND.
I'M GLAD WE CAN AGREE
ON SOMETHING.
DO YOU RECOGNIZE THIS?
IT BELONGED TO ZEFRAM COCHRANE.
HE USED IT TO KILL
THE FIRST VULCAN
WHO STEPPED ONTO TERRAN SOIL.
I WONDER HOW HISTORY
WOULD HAVE PLAYED OUT
IF COCHRANE HADN'T TURNED THE
TABLES ON YOUR INVASION FORCE.
HUMANS MIGHT BE YOUR SLAVES
INSTEAD OF THE OTHER WAY AROUND.
I'M NOT A SLAVE.
YOU'RE VULCAN.
NEVER FORGET THAT.
HOW LONG UNTIL WE CROSS
INTO THOLIAN SPACE?
IT'S LIKELY WE ALREADY HAVE.
THEY FREQUENTLY ANNEX SYSTEMS
OUTSIDE THEIR CORE TERRITORY.
THERE'S A WARP SIGNATURE
ENCODED ON THIS.
NOTIFY ME THE MOMENT
YOU FIND IT.
-IF THERE'S NOTHING FURTHER --
-THERE IS.
I'M PROMOTING YOU
TO FIRST OFFICER.
MAJOR REED'S NEXT IN LINE.
HE WON'T BE PLEASED --
REED IS A CAPABLE SOLDIER,
BUT HE HAS TROUBLE
FOLLOWING ORDERS.
AND I KNOW HE HAS AMBITIONS
OF HIS OWN.
YOU'VE MADE IT CLEAR
YOU DON'T APPROVE OF VULCANS.
MAYBE THIS IS MY WAY
OF SAYING THANK YOU
TO YOU AND YOUR PEOPLE.
WITHOUT VULCAN TECHNOLOGY,
THE EMPIRE WOULDN'T BE
WHERE IT IS TODAY.
DISMISSED.
SERVING AS MY PERSONAL GUARD
WILL HAVE ITS PRIVILEGES.
YOU'LL HAVE YOUR OWN QUARTERS,
BETTER FOOD.
YOU'LL ACCEPT ORDERS FROM ME,
AND ME ALONE. IS THAT CLEAR?
YES, SIR.
AND CAPTAIN, IF I MAY,
I'D LIKE TO BE THE FIRST
TO CONGRATULATE YOU
ON A BRILLIANT STRATEGY.
I'M CERTAIN THAT
IN YEARS TO COME --
YOU ALREADY HAVE THE JOB,
SERGEANT.
DON'T TALK YOURSELF OUT OF IT.
[ DOG GROWLING ]
DON'T MIND PORTHOS.
HE HASN'T HAD HIS DINNER YET.
-[ DOOR CHIMES ]
-COME IN.
THAT'LL BE ALL.
YOU DIDN'T RECEIVE
A COMMUNIQUé FROM STARFLEET.
I WOULD HAVE KNOWN
IF SOMETHING CAME THROUGH.
[ PORTHOS RUMBLES ]
[ LAUGHS ]
A MUTINY. OH.
DIDN'T THINK YOU HAD IT IN YOU.
I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A COMPLIMENT.
WHERE'S CAPTAIN FORREST?
HE'S SAFE.
HOW DO I KNOW THAT YOU DIDN'T
PUSH HIM OUT OF AN AIRLOCK?
I WANT TO TALK TO HIM.
-NOT RIGHT NOW.
-[ BEEPS ]
HE'LL REMAIN ALIVE AS LONG
AS YOU DON'T CAUSE ANY TROUBLE.
NO HIDDEN DISTRESS SIGNALS
TO STARFLEET.
I NEED YOU AND YOUR EXPERTISE.
IS THAT ALL YOU NEED?
YOU'VE NEVER
FORGIVEN ME FOR LEAVING.
I'M SORRY IF I HURT YOU.
YOU SAW AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR ADVANCEMENT AND YOU TOOK IT.
JUST AS YOU DID.
YOU SHOULD HAVE BEEN CAPTAIN
FROM THE MOMENT
WE LEFT SPACEDOCK.
YOU'VE ALWAYS KNOWN THAT.
OH, IF IT HADN'T BEEN
FOR ALL THOSE ADMIRALS
CONSPIRING BEHIND YOUR BACK,
ENTERPRISE WOULD HAVE
BEEN YOURS.
TRADITION SAYS THAT WHATEVER...
BELONGED TO
THE PREVIOUS CAPTAIN
IS YOURS FOR THE TAKING.
I'VE NEVER BEEN ONE
TO ARGUE WITH TRADITION.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-T'Pol to Captain Archer.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
KEEP OUR RELATIONSHIP
ON A PROFESSIONAL LEVEL.
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-Captain Archer, please respond.
GO AHEAD.
We're approaching
the warp signature.
ON MY WAY.
I EXPECT YOU TO BE IN A BETTER
MOOD WHEN I GET BACK.
CAPTAIN ON THE BRIDGE.
WE'RE CLOSING ON TARGET.
20,000 KILOMETERS.
THERE'S ONE BIO-SIGN ABOARD.
THOLIAN.
POWER THE TRACTOR EMITTERS.
[ BEEPING ]
HE'S SEEN US.
HE'S ARMING WEAPONS.
[ RUMBLING ]
DISABLE HIS SHIP.
I DON'T WANT THE PILOT INJURED.
DONE.
THERE'S AN OVERLOAD
BUILDING IN HIS REACTOR.
MAJOR?
IT WASN'T MY DOING, SIR.
I TARGETED HIS WEAPONS ONLY.
I BELIEVE THE PILOT
MAY BE ATTEMPTING
TO DESTROY HIS OWN SHIP.
LOCK ON THE TRANSPORTER.
BEAM HIM INTO
THE DECON CHAMBER.
CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE THE PILOT.
ARCHER TO SICKBAY.
WE'VE BEAMED
A THOLIAN INTO DECON.
MODIFY THE ATMOSPHERE
IN THERE.
IT MAY TAKE A MOMENT.
THOLIANS HAVE RATHER EXTREME
LIFE-SUPPORT REQUIREMENTS.
INCREASING TEMPERATURE
TO 480 KELVIN.
[ THOLIAN CHITTERING ]
IF YOU'RE ANGRY NOW,
JUST WAIT.
HOW IS HE?
HOW IS "IT" WOULD
BE MORE ACCURATE.
THOLIANS POSSESS BOTH MALE
AND FEMALE CHARACTERISTICS.
ITS BIO-SIGNS, SUCH AS THEY ARE,
APPEAR TO BE STABLE.
WILL IT UNDERSTAND ME?
[ BEEPS ]
I'M CAPTAIN ARCHER.
YOU'RE ONBOARD
THE TERRAN FLAGSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ANSWER MY QUESTIONS
OR YOU WILL BE HARMED.
[ SHRILL CHITTERING ]
IT'S DEMANDING TO BE RELEASED.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE HOLDING
THE TERRAN VESSEL
YOU CAPTURED.
[ THOLIAN CHITTERING ]
"MY PEOPLE WILL FIND YOUR SHIP
AND DESTROY IT."
A MINOR ADJUSTMENT
TO LIFE SUPPORT
SHOULD MAKE IT
MORE COOPERATIVE.
DECREASING TEMPERATURE
50 DEGREES.
[ CHITTERING ]
TELL ME WHAT I WANT TO KNOW.
SOMETHING ABOUT
YOUR MATERNAL ANCESTOR.
TAKE IT DOWN ANOTHER 50.
[ SHRIEKING ]
ITS EXOSKELETON IS
BEGINNING TO FRACTURE.
"I AGREE. I AGREE."
GO ON.
THE SHIP IS IN
THE VINTAAK SYSTEM,
AT A FACILITY
ORBITING THE GAS GIANT.
[ SHRILLING ]
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
A SHORT-RANGE TRANSMISSION.
A DISTRESS SIGNAL.
YOU THINK IT HAS
A COMM DEVICE IN THERE?
ITS CRYSTALLINE STRUCTURE
MAY ACT AS A NATURAL
TRANSMITTER.
SIR, I RECOMMEND WE BEAM IT
INTO SPACE IMMEDIATELY.
NO. I NEED TO KEEP
IT ALIVE FOR NOW,
UNTIL I CAN VERIFY
WHAT IT'S TOLD US.
FIND SOME WAY
TO KNOCK THAT THING OUT.
YES, CAPTAIN.
YOU FORGET SOMETHING?
BIGGS!
GET THE COMMANDER
A RADIATION METER.
YOU DON'T WANT TO
END UP LIKE ME, DO YOU?
I'VE ABSORBED
ENOUGH DELTA RAYS
TO GUARANTEE MY GRANDCHILDREN
GLOW IN THE DARK.
FLUX COUPLER.
[ MACHINES HUMMING ]
THEY SAY FOR EVERY YEAR
YOU SPEND NEXT TO
ONE OF THESE THINGS,
YOU LOSE A DECADE
OFF YOUR LIFE EXPECTANCY,
WHICH MEANS I'LL PROBABLY BE
DEAD BY THE END OF THE WEEK.
YOU SHOULD SPEAK
TO CAPTAIN ARCHER
ABOUT A PROMOTION.
YOU'RE HIS FIRST OFFICER.
YOU COULD TALK TO HIM FOR ME.
WHY WOULD I DO THAT?
I DID YOU A FAVOR ONCE.
WE AGREED NEVER TO DISCUSS THAT.
AND I HAVEN'T.
I'D HARDLY CALL IT A FAVOR.
YOU ENJOYED YOURSELF.
SEVERAL TIMES, AS I RECALL.
SO, HOW MANY YEARS IS IT
UNTIL YOUR PON FARR
COMES AROUND AGAIN?
[ BUZZING ]
WHERE THE HELL'S
THAT COMING FROM?
[ BUZZING ]
PULL THE MATRIX CONVERTER!
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ GROANING ]
CAN YOU REPAIR THE CLOAK?
-IT'LL TAKE AT LEAST A DAY.
-YOU HAVE 6 HOURS.
THERE ARE DOZENS OF
E.P.S. FEEDS ON THIS DECK.
AND THE ONLY ONE
THAT OVERLOADS
IS THE ONE CONNECTED
TO THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
THE POWER SURGE
DISABLED OTHER SYSTEMS.
INTERNAL SENSORS ARE DOWN.
WE'VE LOST
GRAV-PLATING ON "G" DECK.
THE CLOAK'S
YOUR FIRST PRIORITY.
SOMEONE'S RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED.
FIND OUT WHO.
MY PEOPLE
CAN INVESTIGATE THIS.
I DON'T NEED HIS KIND
CRAWLING AROUND, PULLING RELAYS.
GET THE CLOAK ONLINE.
WHO SABOTAGED THE CLOAK?
WAS SOMETHING DAMAGED?
I KNOW ADMIRAL BLACK
HAS AN AGENT ON ENTERPRISE.
I WANT THE NAME.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THAT THE ADMIRAL
WOULD PLANT A SPY ON MY SHIP,
AND THEN TELL ME WHO IT IS?
GO TO HIS QUARTERS,
SEARCH HIS PERSONAL FILES.
-LOOK FOR MESSAGES
FROM STARFLEET.
-FOLLOW HIS ORDERS,
AND YOU'LL BE EXECUTED
AS A CO-CONSPIRATOR.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
THIS ISN'T LIKE YOU, JONATHAN.
YOU NEVER LUSTED
FOR POWER AND GLORY.
THAT'S WHY I TRUSTED YOU
AT MY SIDE ALL THESE YEARS --
BECAUSE YOU HAVE NO AMBITION.
IF THAT'S RIGHT,
THEN WHY ARE YOU IN THE BRIG?!
[ CHOKING ]
RELEASE ME,
AND I PROMISE
YOUR DEATH WILL BE QUICK.
[ GASPING ]
YOU WON'T GET THAT GUARANTEE
FROM THE ADMIRAL.
[ PANTING ]
KILL ME,
AND SHE'LL NEVER FORGIVE YOU.
[ COUGHING ]
THE SABOTEUR
ENTERED THIS JUNCTION
AND DELIBERATELY OVERLOADED
THIS E.P.S. WAVEGUIDE.
THAT JUNCTION'S
SUPPOSED TO BE OFF-LIMITS.
THE INTRUDER ALARMS
WERE DISABLED.
HOW?
THERE'S ONLY
ONE WAY I KNOW OF --
BY RUNNING
A HIGH-LEVEL DIAGNOSTIC SCAN.
COMMANDER TUCKER
INITIATED A SCAN
30 MINUTES
BEFORE THE OVERLOAD.
[ GROANING ]
[ PANTING ]
WHO ORDERED YOU
TO SABOTAGE THE CLOAK?
I DIDN'T!
[ ELECTRICITY SURGING ]
[ GROANS ]
REED, I'LL KILL YOU
WHEN I GET OUT OF THIS!
I'D LIKE TO SEE YOU TRY.
I CHECKED THE RECORDS.
ADMIRAL BLACK RECOMMENDED YOU
FOR CHIEF ENGINEER.
HE INSISTED FORREST REPLACE
HIS OWN MAN WITH YOU.
YOU'RE WORKING
FOR THE ADMIRAL, AREN'T YOU?
WHAT HAVE YOU TOLD HIM?
CAPTAIN,
YOU'VE GOT IT ALL WRONG.
[ ELECTRICITY SURGING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ GASPING ]
-IT WASN'T ME!
-WHAT HAVE YOU TOLD HIM?
PLEASE, CAPTAIN.
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN LOYAL TO YOU!
BREAK HIM.
[ GROANING ]
IT HASN'T BEEN THAT GOOD
IN A LONG TIME.
[ SIGHS ]
THE THINGS A GIRL
WILL GIVE UP FOR HER CAREER.
THE DATA I GAVE YOU,
DID YOU TRANSMIT IT
TO THE FLEET ADMIRAL?
OF COURSE.
WHAT WAS IT?
INSURANCE POLICY.
WHAT'S WRONG?
TUCKER'S A COMPETENT ENGINEER.
IF HE WANTED TO
DAMAGE THE CLOAK,
HE COULD HAVE DONE
A MUCH BETTER JOB.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN EASY
WITH T'POL LOOKING
OVER HIS SHOULDER.
COMPUTER,
LOCATE COMMANDER T'POL.
UNABLE TO COMPLY.
INTERNAL SENSORS ARE OFFLINE.
THE SENSORS WERE DAMAGED
BY THE OVERLOAD.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
STAY HERE.
[ EXPLOSION ]
I WONDERED
WHAT WAS KEEPING YOU.
-I NEEDED TIME TO FIND HELP.
-NO ALARM?
I'VE DISABLED THE INTERNAL
SENSORS AND THE COMM SYSTEM.
WE'LL TAKE THE BRIDGE FIRST.
SET A COURSE OUT
OF THOLIAN SPACE, MAXIMUM WARP.
I CAN'T ALTER OUR HEADING.
FULL STOP!
THE HELM'S NOT RESPONDING.
HAVING TROUBLE?
YOU DID THIS.
AUTONAVIGATION
CAN'T BE RELEASED
UNTIL WE'VE REACHED
THE COORDINATES I'VE SET.
RESTORE THE CONTROLS NOW.
I CAN'T.
THEY'VE BEEN ENCRYPTED
WITH A RANDOM CODE.
CAN YOU OVERRIDE THE HELM?
IT'LL TAKE SEVERAL DAYS
TO BREAK THE ENCRYPTION.
WE'LL ARRIVE AT THE COORDINATES
LONG BEFORE THEN.
THE BRIDGE IS YOURS, CAPTAIN.
[ GROANING ]
10 HOURS IN THE BOOTH.
IMPRESSIVE.
GET HIM OUT OF THERE.
BRING MAJOR REED.
I WANT HIM TO SPEND SOME TIME
IN THIS INVENTION OF HIS.
MM.
YOU GONNA S-SHOOT ME NOW
OR WAIT FOR COURT-MARTIAL?
FLEET ADMIRAL GARDNER'S
ORDERED YOU RELEASED.
HE RECEIVED THE DATA
YOU SENT HIM.
THE ADMIRAL FINDS
YOUR SUGGESTION INTRIGUING.
SINCE YOU'VE ALREADY LOCKED US
ON THIS COURSE,
I'VE BEEN ORDERED TO INVESTIGATE
YOUR MYSTERY SHIP.
YOU BETRAYED ME.
DON'T THINK FOR ONE MOMENT
I'M GOING TO FORGET THAT.
GET CLEANED UP.
YOU'RE BRIEFING
THE SENIOR STAFF IN AN HOUR.
A PARALLEL UNIVERSE.
THE SCIENCE DIRECTORATE
HAS EXAMINED ALL THESE THEORIES.
THEY'VE FOUND NO EVIDENCE
OF ALTERNATE REALITIES.
THE THOLIANS ARE
A LITTLE MORE OPEN-MINDED
THAN YOUR PEOPLE.
THEY DETONATED
A TRICOBALT WARHEAD HERE,
INSIDE THE GRAVITY WELL
OF A DEAD STAR.
THE EXPLOSION
CREATED AN INTERPHASIC RIFT,
A DOORWAY INTO
ANOTHER UNIVERSE.
-A DOORWAY.
-THE RIFT WAS UNSTABLE.
IT WAS TOO DANGEROUS TO SEND
ONE OF THEIR OWN SHIPS THROUGH.
SO THEY TRANSMITTED A DISTRESS
CALL INTO THE OPENING,
HOPING TO LURE A SHIP
FROM THE OTHER SIDE.
THEIR PLAN WORKED BRILLIANTLY.
HOW DID YOU LEARN ALL THIS?
THE THOLIANS RELY
ON OUTSIDE LABORERS.
HUMANOIDS.
SOME OF THEM CAN BE BOUGHT
FOR THE RIGHT PRICE.
I HOPE YOU DIDN'T PAY
TOO MUCH.
MY CONTACT TRANSMITTED
THESE IMAGES
BEFORE HIS SIGNAL WAS JAMMED.
YOU CAN BARELY SEE ANYTHING.
COMPUTER,
ENHANCE GRID 3-ALPHA.
AN EARTH SHIP?
ACCORDING TO SOME THEORIES,
EVERYTHING THAT EXISTS
IN OUR UNIVERSE
SHOULD ALSO EXIST THERE.
ANOTHER TERRAN EMPIRE?
ANOTHER STARFLEET?
SO WHAT?
HOW DOES THIS HELP US?
THE THOLIANS QUANTUM-DATED
A PIECE OF THE HULL.
THIS SHIP IS NOT ONLY
FROM ANOTHER UNIVERSE,
IT'S FROM ANOTHER TIME --
ABOUT 100 YEARS INTO THE FUTURE.
IMAGINE THE TECHNOLOGY
WE CAN FIND ON THAT SHIP.
NEW TACTICAL SYSTEMS,
ADVANCED BIO-WEAPONS,
ENGINES THAT CAN REACH SPEEDS
WE CAN ONLY DREAM OF.
ALL OF IT OURS FOR THE TAKING.
THIS IS LUDICROUS, CAPTAIN.
SOMEONE HAS FABRICATED
THIS EVIDENCE TO LURE US HERE.
COMMANDER ARCHER IS GUILTY
OF ASSAULT AND MUTINY.
THAT'S ENOUGH, COMMANDER.
SIR, I BELIEVE WE SHOULD --
I SAID SHUT UP!
WE'RE INVESTIGATING THIS.
GET THAT CLOAKING DEVICE
WORKING.
THE CAPTAIN WANTS
A PROGRESS REPORT.
I'LL NEED ANOTHER MINUTE TO
CALIBRATE THE FIELD CONVERTERS.
I SPENT 4 HOURS IN THE BOOTH
BECAUSE OF YOU.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD DIRECT
YOUR ANGER AT COMMANDER ARCHER.
YOU DISABLED THE ALARMS
IN THAT JUNCTION
AND MADE IT LOOK LIKE
I DID IT.
-YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
-THE HELL I AM!
I THINK I'D REMEMBER
IF I HAD SABOTAGED THE SHIP!
NOT NECESSARILY.
WHAT DID YOU DO TO ME?
I LURED YOU AWAY
FROM ENGINEERING
WITH THE PROMISE
OF A SEXUAL ENCOUNTER.
MY MIND TO YOUR MIND.
ONCE WE WERE ALONE
IN MY QUARTERS,
I IMPLANTED
A TELEPATHIC SUGGESTION.
MY THOUGHTS TO YOUR THOUGHTS.
I COMPELLED YOU
TO SABOTAGE THE POWER GRID.
AFTER YOU
COMPLETED THE ASSIGNMENT,
WE MELDED AGAIN.
I ALTERED YOUR MEMORY
OF WHAT HAD HAPPENED.
IT WAS MY DUTY TO HELP
CAPTAIN FORREST REGAIN COMMAND.
YOU'RE GONNA REGRET
WHAT YOU DID.
THREATS ARE ILLOGICAL.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
-Go ahead.
-WE'RE READY.
I'm gonna have to
channel everything
except auxiliary power.
ENGAGE THE CLOAK.
[ BEEPING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
WE'VE REACHED
THE COORDINATES.
AUTONAVIGATION
HAS DISENGAGED.
LET'S SEE WHERE WE ARE.
MAGNIFY THE MOON
ON THE FAR RIGHT.
PRIMARY SYSTEMS ARE OFFLINE,
INCLUDING LIFE SUPPORT.
WE'RE READING 13 BIO-SIGNS,
ALL ALIEN.
ONE OF THEM
APPEARS TO BE REPTILIAN.
THEY'RE CLUSTERED
IN THIS SECTION.
ANY SIGN OF THE CREW?
WE'VE DETECTED
NO HUMAN SIGNATURES.
IT'S LIKELY
THE CREW WAS EXECUTED.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THOSE COILS.
I'LL BET THAT THING
COULD DO WARP 7.
WE'LL SEND
AN ASSAULT TEAM ABOARD.
YOU BROUGHT US HERE.
YOU LEAD IT.
DOWNLOAD WHATEVER YOU CAN
FROM THE DATABASE.
THEN DESTROY THE SHIP.
DESTROY IT?
WE HAVE TO TAKE
THE SHIP WITH US.
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
WE ARE DEEP IN THOLIAN SPACE.
SIR, YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS!
DISMISSED.
GO WITH HIM.
I DON'T WANT ARCHER TO RETURN
FROM THIS MISSION.
DO I MAKE MYSELF CLEAR,
COMMANDER?
Someone's removed
these components.
They're gutting the ship.
[ BEEPING ]
Human.
If you like, sir,
I could hold that for you.
[ THOLIAN CHITTERING ]
NAPTIME ISN'T OVER YET.
[ BEEPING ]
I'M PICKING UP A TRANSMISSION.
IT'S COMING FROM DECON.
BRIDGE TO PHLOX.
What's happening down there?
THE SEDATIVE
IS NO LONGER WORKING.
-Well, then kill it now!
-WITH PLEASURE.
[ SHRIEKING ]
THREE SHIPS ARE MOVING
TOWARD OUR POSITION.
DOCTOR?
A FEW MORE SECONDS, CAPTAIN.
WILL YOU KINDLY DIE?
[ SCREECHING ]
-[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPS ]
-PHLOX TO BRIDGE.
You won't be having any further
trouble from our guest.
-[ BEEPING ]
-ONE OF THE THOLIAN SHIPS
IS HAILING US.
THIS MUST BE THE CAPTAIN.
HIS NECK'S BROKEN.
[ BEEPING ]
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO OVERLOAD
THE REACTOR FROM HERE.
GET STARTED.
FOUR MORE SHIPS.
CONTACT ARCHER.
TELL HIM TO ABORT THE MISSION.
LAY IN A COURSE OUT OF HERE.
THEY'RE JAMMING US.
TARGET THE NEAREST SHIP.
FIRE!
[ BUZZING ]
NO DAMAGE.
TORPEDO LAUNCHERS,
FIRE WHEN READY.
[ TORPEDOES FIRING ]
THEY CAN SEE US.
[ EXPLOSION ]
GET US OUT OF HERE.
ENGINEERING,
DISENGAGE THE CLOAK
AND TRANSFER
ALL POWER TO ENGINES.
Cloak's not responding, sir.
[ EXPLOSION ]
HOW MUCH LONGER?
MAYBE YOU'D LIKE
TO TAKE A STAB AT IT.
I CAN ACTIVATE THEIR SYSTEMS.
-STAND ASIDE, COMMANDER.
-ALMOST THERE.
[ BEEPING ]
[ HUMMING ]
[ ALARM BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE IS UNDER ATTACK.
HULL PLATING'S DOWN.
WE'VE LOST POWER ON
DECKS "C," "D," AND "E."
Engineering to bridge.
The containment fields
are failing.
CAN YOU VENT THE ANTIMATTER?
Negative.
Reactor breach in 3 minutes.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
ALL HANDS TO ESCAPE PODS.
ABANDON SHIP.
YOU HEARD MY ORDER!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
I'LL BUY YOU
AS MUCH TIME AS I CAN.
GET OUT OF HERE NOW.
ENTERPRISE IS
TAKING HEAVY DAMAGE.
CAN YOU BRING
WEAPONS AND ENGINES ONLINE?
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
GIVE ME A HAND WITH THEM!
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
COMMANDER.