PREVIOUSLY ON "ENTERPRISE"...
A PARALLEL UNIVERSE.
ACCORDING TO SOME THEORIES,
EVERYTHING THAT EXISTS
IN OUR UNIVERSE
SHOULD ALSO EXIST THERE.
ANOTHER TERRAN EMPIRE?
ANOTHER STARFLEET?
I'M NOT A SLAVE.
YOU'RE VULCAN.
NEVER FORGET THAT.
THE THINGS A GIRL
WILL GIVE UP FOR HER CAREER.
THIS SHIP IS NOT ONLY
FROM ANOTHER UNIVERSE,
IT'S FROM ANOTHER TIME --
ABOUT 100 YEARS INTO THE FUTURE.
IMAGINE THE TECHNOLOGY
WE CAN FIND ON THAT SHIP.
OURS FOR THE TAKING.
ENTERPRISE IS UNDER ATTACK.
THE THOLIANS CAN SEE US.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
ALL HANDS TO ESCAPE PODS.
ABANDON SHIP.
COMMANDER!
[ BEEPING ]
YOU'VE GOT THRUSTERS.
RELEASE THE DOCKING CLAMPS.
-I CAN'T.
-WHAT ABOUT WEAPONS?
[ BEEPING ]
THIS POWER GRID'S A MESS.
IT'S GONNA TAKE A FEW MINUTES.
SIR, THE SHIELDS
ARE FUNCTIONAL.
-RAISE THEM.
-[ CLANKING ]
THE SHIELDS
ARE WEAKENING THE CLAMPS,
BUT THEY'RE STILL HOLDING.
I'LL ALTERNATE PORT
AND STARBOARD THRUSTERS.
THAT SHOULD SHAKE THEM LOOSE.
WE'RE FREE.
[ BEEPING ]
FIRING AFT THRUSTERS.
SIX THOLIAN SHIPS
MOVING TOWARD US.
HOW MUCH LONGER FOR WEAPONS?
THE POWER COUPLINGS
HAVE BEEN REMOVED.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN BYPASS THEM.
SIR.
[ MACHINE BEEPING ]
-MR. TUCKER.
-STAND BY.
I COULD USE
SOME HELP OVER HERE.
WHEN I TELL YOU, SHUNT THE
PLASMA TO THE FORWARD EMITTERS.
THREE MORE SHIPS APPROACHING.
JUST A FEW MORE SECONDS.
-[ EXPLOSION ]
-WHAT WAS THAT?
THEY'VE LOCKED ON
A TRACTOR BEAM.
WE'RE BEING PULLED BACK
INTO THE DOCK.
IT'S NOW OR NEVER!
STAND BY!
NOW!
[ MACHINE HUMMING ]
-[ BEEPING ]
-TACTICAL SYSTEMS ARE ONLINE.
[ REVVING ]
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ BEEPING ]
FULL THRUSTERS.
THE REMAINING SHIPS
ARE RETREATING.
THE STATION'S OPENED FIRE.
DOES THIS THING
HAVE AFT TORPEDOES?
YOU BETTER BELIEVE IT.
THEY'RE ARMED.
[ BEEPING ]
ESCAPE PODS.
12 KILOMETERS OFF THE PORT BOW.
THEY'RE OURS.
BRING THEM ONBOARD.
WE NEED WARP DRIVE.
ENGINEERING'S BEEN STRIPPED
TO THE BULKHEADS.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS IS,
MOST OF WHAT THEY TOOK
WAS STILL SITTING
IN MY HANGAR DECK.
BUT I NEED TIME TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO PUT IT ALL BACK TOGETHER.
HOW MUCH TIME?
TWO OR THREE DAYS.
SIR, I'M NOT EVEN SURE
WHAT SOME OF THESE SYSTEMS
ARE SUPPOSED TO DO.
IT'S LIKE I'M CHIEF ENGINEER
ON A STEAMSHIP
COMING ABOARD THE FIRST
INTERPLANETARY TRANSPORT.
IF WE DON'T HAVE
WARP CAPABILITY IN 12 HOURS,
I'M GOING TO FIND
A NEW CHIEF ENGINEER.
I SUGGEST WE MAKE USE
OF THE ALIEN WORKERS.
THEY MAY KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT THESE SYSTEMS.
KEEP THEM UNDER CLOSE
SURVEILLANCE.
ONCE WARP DRIVE IS RESTORED,
WE'LL SET A COURSE TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE ASSAULT FLEET.
WE'RE IN NO CONDITION
FOR BATTLE.
WE MADE QUICK WORK
OF THE THOLIANS.
THIS SHIP IS DESIGNED TO BE
OPERATED BY A CREW OF 400.
THERE ARE ONLY 47 OF US.
THE LOGICAL COURSE OF ACTION
IS TO TAKE DEFIANT TO EARTH,
ALLOW STARFLEET TO STUDY IT,
-REVERSE-ENGINEER
ITS SYSTEMS --
-THERE'S NO TIME!
THE EMPIRE COULD LOSE THIS WAR
IN A MATTER OF WEEKS
IF WE DON'T GET THE DEFIANT
AND ITS WEAPONS
TO THE FRONT LINES.
DISMISSED!
COMMANDER.
NOT YOU.
I SHOULD SHOOT YOU
FOR BETRAYING ME.
THE ORDERS GIVING YOU
COMMAND OF ENTERPRISE
WERE OBVIOUSLY FABRICATED.
IT WAS MY DUTY
AS A STARFLEET OFFICER
TO HELP CAPTAIN FORREST
REGAIN CONTROL OF HIS SHIP.
YOU SWORE YOUR LOYALTY TO ME.
YOU SHOULD BE AWARE
CAPTAIN FORREST
ORDERED ME TO KILL YOU.
WHY ARE YOU TELLING ME THIS?
FORREST IS DEAD.
HIS ORDERS ARE NO LONGER VALID.
YOU ARE MY COMMANDING OFFICER.
I NEVER HAD A PROBLEM
WITH YOUR PEOPLE...
...UNTIL THEY BECAME A PART
OF THIS REBELLION.
IF I HAD ANOTHER OFFICER
CAPABLE OF DOING YOUR JOB,
I'D SHOW YOU
TO THE NEAREST AIRLOCK.
I NEED YOU TO GET THIS SHIP
UP AND RUNNING.
BUT IF I HEAR SO MUCH
AS A RUMOR THAT YOU'RE WORKING
BEHIND MY BACK --
-UNDERSTOOD.
-GET OUT.
[ LAUGHS ]
WHAT ARE YOU WEARING?
I FOUND IT
IN THE CAPTAIN'S WARDROBE.
THESE PEOPLE HAD SOME
STRANGE IDEAS ABOUT UNIFORMS.
I CAN'T FIND A MENTION
OF IT ANYWHERE.
A MENTION OF WHAT?
THE EMPIRE.
AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
IT DOESN'T EXIST
IN THE OTHER UNIVERSE.
NO EMPIRE?
A LOT OF THE NAMES
ARE THE SAME,
BUT THEIR HISTORY
HAS BEEN REWRITTEN.
INSTEAD OF BUILDING AN EMPIRE,
EARTH BECAME PART
OF AN INTERSPECIES ALLIANCE.
THE UNITED FEDERATION
OF PLANETS?
MORE LIKE A FEDERATION
OF FOOLS.
WHAT ABOUT US?
DO WE EXIST IN THIS UNIVERSE?
COMPUTER, ACCESS
BIOGRAPHICAL FILE,
STARFLEET OFFICER HOSHI SATO.
WORKING.
[ COMPUTER WHIRRING ]
[ BEEPING ]
"HOSHI SATO.
"COMM OFFICER ON STARFLEET'S
FIRST WARP-5 SHIP.
"IN HER LATE 30s,
SHE CREATED THE LINGUACODE
TRANSLATION MATRIX."
AT LEAST SHE WAS REMEMBERED
FOR SOMETHING.
I CAN TELL YOU WHO SHE MARRIED.
IT EVEN SAYS HOW YOU DIE.
STOP. I DON'T WANT TO KNOW.
-BUT THIS ISN'T YOU --
-I DON'T CARE.
COMPUTER.
[ BEEPING ]
DISPLAY FILE ON STARFLEET
OFFICER JONATHAN ARCHER.
WORKING.
[ COMPUTER WHIRRING ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
OH.
"SON OF FAMED
WARP SPECIALIST HENRY ARCHER,
"JONATHAN WAS APPOINTED
"CAPTAIN OF STARFLEET'S
FIRST WARP-5 SHIP.
"HIS NAME IS AMONG
THE MOST RECOGNIZED
"IN THE FEDERATION.
"HE EARNED AN IMPRESSIVE
LIST OF COMMENDATIONS
"DURING HIS CAREER.
"HISTORIANS CALLED HIM
THE GREATEST EXPLORER
OF THE 22nd CENTURY."
[ SIGHS ]
"TWO PLANETS
WERE NAMED AFTER HIM."
-[ BEEPS ]
-HEY!
THERE'S NOTHING GREAT
ABOUT THAT MAN.
HE SOLD OUT EARTH'S FUTURE
TO A GROUP OF
SUBHUMAN SPECIES.
GREAT MEN
ARE NOT PEACEMAKERS.
GREAT MEN ARE CONQUERORS!
FORGET ABOUT HIM.
YOUR FUTURE IS JUST BEGINNING.
[ SIGHS ]
CAN YOU IMAGINE THE LOOK
ON THE EMPEROR'S FACE
WHEN HE SEES THIS SHIP?
YOU'LL BE DECLARED
HERO OF THE EMPIRE.
STARFLEET WILL HAVE TO GIVE YOU
A COMMAND OF YOUR OWN.
I ALREADY HAVE
A COMMAND OF MY OWN.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
COMMANDER, SOMEBODY PULLED
BOTH PLASMA REGULATORS
OUT OF THESE HOUSINGS.
WHY ARE YOU BOTHERING ME
WITH THIS?
THEY'RE PROBABLY
ON THE HANGAR DECK.
NO, SIR, YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THEY WERE HERE 10 MINUTES AGO.
I WENT TO GET THIS COUPLER.
WHEN I CAME BACK,
THE REGULATORS WERE GONE.
YOU'D BETTER FIND THEM
BECAUSE IF THIS JUNCTION'S
NOT ONLINE IN 10 MINUTES,
I'M GONNA TELL ARCHER
YOU'RE THE REASON
WE DON'T HAVE WARP DRIVE!
YES. YES, SIR.
[ RATTLING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
WHO'S IN HERE?
[ CREATURE SNARLING ]
[ SUTTON SCREAMING ]
I FOUND TRACES OF REPTILIAN
SALIVA IN THE ENSIGN'S WOUNDS.
SOMETHING BIT HIM?
MM, THE BITE RADIUS
WOULD SUGGEST
A PARTICULARLY LARGE REPTILE
MORE THAN 2 METERS IN LENGTH.
CAN YOU FIND THIS THING
ON INTERNAL SENSORS?
IT'S NOT IN THE PRIMARY HULL.
SENSORS ARE STILL OFFLINE
ON THE ENGINEERING DECKS.
PERHAPS IT WAS A PET OWNED
BY ONE OF THE ORIGINAL CREW.
UNLESS ONE OF THEM
OWNED A VELOCIRAPTOR,
I FIND IT EXTREMELY UNLIKELY.
-[ DOOR OPENING ]
-THERE'S NO SIGN
OF THE REGULATORS.
WITHOUT THEM, WE CAN'T
INITIALIZE THE REACTION CHAMBER.
WE'RE STUCK AT IMPULSE.
WHOEVER SABOTAGED US
KNEW EXACTLY
WHICH COMPONENTS TO STEAL.
THE SLAVES WE CAPTURED --
BRING ONE OF THEM
TO THE BRIEFING ROOM.
CERTAINLY, SIR.
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GROANING ]
WHAT ATTACKED MY CREWMAN?
HE PROMISED HE'D KILL US
IF WE TOLD YOU.
I'LL KILL YOU NOW
IF YOU DON'T.
[ SOBBING ] PLEASE!
STAND ASIDE.
-[ SOBBING ]
-T'POL TO MAJOR REED.
-BRING ANOTHER PRISONER
TO THE BRIEFING ROOM.
-Acknowledged.
FROM WHAT I'M TOLD,
THE MAXIMUM SETTING
CAN ACTUALLY
DISINTEGRATE A PERSON.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FORWARD
TO TRYING IT.
[ GASPING ]
HIS NAME IS SLAR.
WHOSE NAME?
OUR SLAVE MASTER.
[ GULPING ]
HE WAS IN CHARGE
OF THE SALVAGE OPERATION.
WHEN YOU BOARDED THE SHIP,
HE HID IN
THE SERVICE CRAWLWAYS.
[ SOBBING ]
HE WAS PLANNING
TO SABOTAGE THE SHIP.
WHERE IN THE CRAWLWAYS?
POSSIBLY NEAR
THE POWER-TRANSFER CONDUITS
ON DECK 22.
IT'S WARM THERE.
HIS SPECIES LIKES IT WARM.
WHAT SPECIES?
GORN.
HE'S -- HE'S A GORN.
[ CRYING ]
WE HAD IT CORNERED
IN TURBOSHAFT 3,
BUT IT APPEARS TO HAVE ESCAPED
THROUGH THIS ACCESS TUBE.
THAT'S WHEN WE LOST CONTACT
WITH McKENZIE AND BROWNE.
THEY'RE TAKING TOO LONG.
WHEN MY SHIP WAS IN JEOPARDY,
I DIDN'T LET SECURITY
HANDLE THE SITUATION.
I TOOK CARE OF IT MYSELF.
I'D HAVE BETTER LUCK
SENDING A SQUAD
OF TELLARITES
TO CAPTURE THIS THING.
PUT AN ASSAULT TEAM TOGETHER.
I'LL LEAD IT MYSELF.
[ BEEPING ]
SIR, I'M PICKING UP A SIGNAL
FROM INSIDE THE SHIP.
I THINK IT'S THE REPTILE.
CAN YOU PINPOINT ITS LOCATION?
THE FREQUENCY'S SCRAMBLED.
I WANT TO TALK TO IT.
THE TRANSLATOR MATRIX
IS TIED IN.
THIS IS CAPTAIN ARCHER.
RETURN OUR PLASMA
REGULATORS NOW.
I want to leave this ship.
GIVE ME WHAT I WANT
AND WE'LL TALK.
No. I'm familiar
with your species.
Humans are not trustworthy.
YOU WILL GIVE ME
A SHUTTLECRAFT!
ONCE I'M AWAY FROM THIS SHIP,
I'LL TELL YOU
WHERE TO FIND THE REGULATORS.
THIS IS NOT A NEGOTIATION!
THE REGULATORS NOW!
IF YOU DON'T COMPLY,
-I'LL GIVE THE ORDER --
-[ BEEP ]
HE CLOSED THE CHANNEL.
MAJOR, GET THE TEAM TOGETHER.
YOUR BEST MEN.
THE GORN'S OFFER
IS REASONABLE.
HE HAS NO INTENTION
OF RETURNING THE REGULATORS.
IF WE GIVE HIM A SHUTTLE,
HE'LL CONTACT HIS PEOPLE
AND COME BACK WITH A WARSHIP!
WITHOUT WARP DRIVE,
WE'LL BE AN EASY TARGET.
DEFEAT THIS GORN
AND YOU'LL FINALLY EARN
THE RESPECT YOU DESERVE.
[ SCANNER BEEPING ]
THERE'S A BIO-SIGN,
VERY FAINT,
IN ACCESS TUBE 7-ALPHA,
NEAR JUNCTION 3.
I'LL SEAL OFF
THE BULKHEAD HERE.
THAT'LL LEAVE HIM
WITH ONLY ONE ESCAPE ROUTE.
FLUSH HIM OUT,
DRIVE HIM INTO THIS JUNCTION.
I'LL BE WAITING FOR HIM.
UNDERSTOOD.
[ BEEPING ]
REED TO CAPTAIN ARCHER.
-Go ahead.
-IT'S NOT HERE.
He's modified a communicator
to emit a false bio-sign.
MEET US IN JUNCTION 3.
Acknowledged.
-[ BEEPING ]
-SHUT THAT BLOODY THING OFF.
IT'S A TRAP!
I'VE FAILED YOU, CAPTAIN.
ARCHER TO T'POL.
WHERE IS IT?
The Gorn's moved
into the primary hull.
IT'S ON DECK 9.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAN "B."
ACCESS THE ENVIRONMENTAL
CONTROLS ON THAT DECK.
WAIT FOR MY SIGNAL.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[ METAL CLANKING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GROWLING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SNARLING ]
[ GROWLING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
ARCHER TO T'POL.
SECTION 4A, ON MY MARK.
Standing by.
NOW!
ENHANCING GRAV PLATING.
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Grav plating's at 20 G's.
[ SLAR GROWLING ]
GIVE ME YOUR WEAPON.
DEFIANT STARLOG,
JANUARY 18, 2155.
WE'VE RECOVERED THE MISSING
ENGINE COMPONENTS
AND I'VE ORDERED A COURSE
TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE ASSAULT FLEET.
WHAT'S MAJOR REED'S CONDITION?
[ SIGHS ]
AT THIS POINT,
HE COULD GO EITHER WAY.
NO DOUBT, THERE'LL BE SEVERAL
DISCREET CELEBRATIONS
IF HE SHOULD EXPIRE.
I NOTICE YOU'VE BEEN
MAKING EXTENSIVE USE
OF THE LIBRARY DATABASE.
I WAS MERELY RESEARCHING
CLASSICAL LITERATURE.
I WANTED TO COMPARE
OUR MAJOR WORKS
WITH THEIR COUNTERPARTS
IN THE OTHER UNIVERSE.
I SKIMMED A FEW OF THE MORE
CELEBRATED NARRATIVES.
THE STORIES WERE SIMILAR
IN SOME RESPECTS
BUT THEIR CHARACTERS
WERE WEAK AND COMPASSIONATE.
WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF SHAKESPEARE, OF COURSE.
FROM WHAT I COULD TELL,
HIS PLAYS WERE EQUALLY GRIM
IN BOTH UNIVERSES.
EXAMINE THEIR HISTORICAL FILES.
YOU MAY WANT TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THEIR FEDERATION.
DID YOU KNOW,
IN THE OTHER UNIVERSE,
HUMANS AND DENOBULANS
ARE CONSIDERED EQUALS,
AS ARE VULCANS.
HMM.
YOU DON'T FIND
THIS INTERESTING.
I FIND IT DANGEROUS.
IF I WERE THE CAPTAIN,
I'D RESTRICT ACCESS
TO THAT DATABASE.
I'M CERTAIN HE WOULDN'T WANT
TO GIVE HIS CREW ANY IDEAS, HMM?
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD RECONSIDER
THE REPERCUSS--
-[ ALARM BLARING ]
-This is the captain.
All hands to battle stations.
REPORT!
HULL BREACH ON "B" DECK.
EMERGENCY BULKHEADS ARE ENGAGED.
CONCENTRATE YOUR FIRE
ON THE ANDORIANS!
HULL PLATING'S AT 32%.
ADMIRAL, THERE'S
ANOTHER VESSEL APPROACHING.
MORE REBELS?
NO.
DIRECT HITS.
THE TELLARITE SHIP'S
OPENED FIRE.
NO DAMAGE.
LOCK ON THEIR REACTOR.
FIRE WHEN READY.
[ MACHINE BEEPING ]
TARGET DESTROYED.
THE VULCAN SHIP'S
TRYING TO ESCAPE.
PURSUIT COURSE.
CAPTAIN,
THEY'RE NO THREAT TO US.
-I RECOMMEND WE --
-FIRE WHEN READY.
THE LAST ANDORIAN SHIP
IS RETREATING.
-WEAPONS ARE LOCKED.
-NO. LET THEM GO.
I WANT THE OTHER REBELS
TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
GET ME ADMIRAL BLACK.
ARCHER?
SORRY WE'RE LATE
FOR THE PARTY, ADMIRAL.
WHERE'S ENTERPRISE?
IS CAPTAIN FORREST WITH YOU?
IT'S GOING TO TAKE
SOME TIME TO EXPLAIN, SIR.
PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE TO SEE
THE DEFIANT FOR YOURSELF.
A MOST IMPRESSIVE VESSEL,
COMMANDER.
WITH THE TECHNOLOGY
ON THIS SHIP AT OUR DISPOSAL,
THE REBELS
WON'T STAND A CHANCE.
GLAD YOU AGREE, SIR.
I INTEND TO RECOMMEND
THAT YOU GET YOUR OWN COMMAND
-AT THE EARLIEST OPPORTUNITY.
-RESPECTFULLY, SIR,
YOU HAVE THE AUTHORITY TO GRANT
A BATTLEFIELD PROMOTION.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE DON'T
HAVE A SHIP TO GIVE YOU
AT THE MOMENT.
THE DEFIANT.
I'M SURE THE FLEET ADMIRAL
HAS OTHER PLANS FOR THIS SHIP.
THEY'RE NEVER GOING TO GIVE YOU
THIS SHIP. YOU KNOW THAT.
THEY'LL TEAR IT APART,
TRY TO LEARN ITS SECRETS.
IF YOU'RE LUCKY, YOU'LL END UP
COMMANDING A MOON SHUTTLE.
...WITH ANY LUCK, WE SHOULD...
DON'T YOU SEE WHAT
THE ADMIRAL'S PLANNING?
HE'S GOING TO PRESENT THIS SHIP
TO THE EMPEROR HIMSELF.
HE'LL TAKE ALL THE CREDIT,
AND YOU'LL END UP
AN HISTORICAL FOOTNOTE.
...ALTER THE COURSE OF THE WAR.
THE PEOPLE OF THE EARTH
ARE IN YOUR DEBT, COMMANDER.
THAT'S CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE RELIEVED, ADMIRAL.
[ SCREAMING ]
OUR ENTIRE ASSAULT FLEET
WIPED OUT BY A REBEL ATTACK.
THOUSANDS OF YOUR FELLOW
STARFLEET OFFICERS DEAD.
IF THE DEFIANT HADN'T
ARRIVED WHEN IT DID,
ALL OF YOU
WOULD BE AMONG THEM.
AND WHO ARE WE
TO BLAME FOR THIS?
NOT THE BRAVE MEN AND WOMEN
WHO GAVE THEIR LIVES
FOR THE EMPIRE.
CRIMINALS
WHO ARE LOSING THIS WAR
ARE SITTING
IN THEIR COMFORTABLE OFFICES
BACK AT STARFLEET COMMAND.
THEIR WEAKNESS
INVITED OUR ENEMIES TO STRIKE
AND THEIR CORRUPTION
AND ARROGANCE
HAVE BROUGHT THE EMPIRE
TO THE BRINK OF DEFEAT!
I'VE BEEN A SOLDIER
ALL MY LIFE,
AND I WILL NOT STAND BY
AND LET THESE PEOPLE
DESTROY AN EMPIRE THAT HAS
ENDURED FOR CENTURIES!
I ASK YOU, ALL OF YOU,
TO JOIN ME.
WE CANNOT PUT DOWN
THIS REBELLION
SO LONG AS OUR FORCES ARE
COMMANDED BY DISHONORABLE MEN.
BEFORE WE CAN DEFEAT THE REBELS,
WE MUST DEFEAT THEM.
THAT SHIP OUT THERE
IS THE KEY TO OUR VICTORY.
WITH THE DEFIANT ON OUR SIDE,
THERE WILL BE
NOTHING TO STOP US.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
ENTER.
IT'S NOT WISE
TO MAKE THAT GESTURE,
EVEN BEHIND CLOSED DOORS.
IT IS AGREEABLE
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
DID YOU REVIEW
THE HISTORICAL FILES?
THE IMPLICATIONS
ARE INTRIGUING.
INTRIGUING?
THIS ALTERNATE UNIVERSE
IS VERY DIFFERENT FROM OURS.
I'M NOT CERTAIN A FEDERATION
COULD EVER EXIST HERE.
I THOUGHT
YOU WERE AN IDEALIST.
-THAT WAS MANY YEARS AGO.
-WE HAVE TO TAKE ACTION!
ARCHER INTENDS TO OVERTHROW
STARFLEET AND THE EMPEROR.
ARCHER IS RIGHT.
THE EMPIRE HAS BECOME CORRUPT.
A NEW LEADER MAY CHANGE THINGS
FOR THE BETTER.
NOT FOR OUR PEOPLE.
WEAPONS ON THAT SHIP
WILL ANNIHILATE THE REBELS,
INCLUDING THOUSANDS
OF VULCANS.
WE CAN GIVE THEM
AN ADVANTAGE.
-HOW?
-I CAN DOWNLOAD THE DATA
ON DEFIANT'S ENGINES
AND TACTICAL SYSTEMS.
WE'LL GIVE IT TO THEM.
DATA WILL BE OF LITTLE VALUE.
ARCHER STILL CONTROLS
THAT SHIP.
-I'M GOING TO DESTROY
-WHAT?
I CAN DISABLE
DEFIANT'S POWER SYSTEMS,
BUT I'LL NEED YOUR HELP.
DO YOU WANT TO SPEND
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE
SERVING THE EMPIRE?
I'M TOO OLD
TO BECOME A REVOLUTIONARY.
I KNOW ARCHER.
HE BLAMES OUR PEOPLE
FOR INCITING THE REBELS.
IF HE BECOMES EMPEROR,
HE'LL LAY WASTE TO VULCAN.
I CAN'T DO THIS WITHOUT YOU.
[ GASPS ]
MY SENIOR OFFICERS
DON'T THINK I CAN DO THIS.
THEY'LL COME AROUND.
T'POL DOESN'T APPROVE EITHER.
I CAN SEE IT IN HER EYES.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO GET RID OF HER
NOW THAT THIS SHIP'S
OPERATIONAL.
NOT JUST HER.
WE'LL GET RID
OF ALL THE NON-TERRANS.
I'LL TRANSFER THEM
OFF DEFIANT.
ALL OF THEM?
THE REBELS HAVE SPIES
EVERYWHERE.
I CAN'T AFFORD
TO HAVE A SINGLE ALIEN
ABOARD MY FLAGSHIP.
I HOPE YOU'RE NOT PLANNING
ON GETTING SICK ANYTIME SOON.
IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
YOUR DOCTOR'S AN ALIEN.
[ MOANING ]
I'VE GOT NOTHING AGAINST PHLOX.
HIS PEOPLE AREN'T REBELS.
IT'S NOT...
IN THEIR NATURE.
HE CAN STAY.
I'VE N-NEVER BEEN THE CONSORT
OF AN EMPEROR BEFORE.
[ MOANING ]
IS THERE ANYTHING
I NEED TO KNOW?
[ PANTING ]
I THINK YOU'VE, UH...
I THINK YOU'VE GOT
THE BASICS DOWN.
[ BEEPING ]
PUT ME THROUGH
TO FLEET ADMIRAL GARDNER.
CORPORAL...
ESCORT COMMANDER T'POL
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM 2.
YOUR SERVICE ABOARD THIS SHIP
IS NO LONGER REQUIRED.
[ BEEPING ]
ARCHER,
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?
I TAKE IT YOU RECEIVED
MY MESSAGE.
YOU DEMANDED STARFLEET'S
UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER!
HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MIND?
YOU'VE SEEN THE SPECS
ON THE DEFIANT.
YOU KNOW
WHAT ITS WEAPONS CAN DO.
I WANT TO SPEAK
WITH ADMIRAL BLACK.
HE'S NOT AVAILABLE RIGHT NOW.
I SUGGEST YOU ORDER YOUR FORCES
TO STAND DOWN.
STARFLEET CAN'T AFFORD
TO LOSE ANY MORE SHIPS.
THIS IS YOUR ONLY WARNING,
COMMANDER.
DO NOT APPROACH EARTH
OR YOU WILL BE FIRED UPON!
Bridge to Doctor Phlox.
THIS IS PHLOX.
There's a medical emergency
on the Avenger.
You're needed immediately.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
NEITHER OF YOU APPEARS
TO BE INJURED.
SABOTAGE THE DEFIANT?
HAVE YOU LOST YOUR SENSES?
YOU'RE THE ONLY
NON-TERRAN ON THE DEFIANT.
ANY OF US WOULD
AROUSE SUSPICION.
YOU HEARD ARCHER'S SPEECH.
HE'S DELUSIONAL.
IT'S NOT A DELUSION
IF THE CAPTAIN HAS THE POWER
TO DO WHAT HE SAYS.
AND FROM WHAT I'VE SEEN,
HE MOST CERTAINLY DOES.
I SHOULD REPORT YOU BOTH.
ARE YOU LOYAL
TO THE EMPIRE OR NOT?
OF COURSE I AM!
ARCHER PLANS TO KILL THE EMPEROR
AND TAKE HIS PLACE.
THE CAPTAIN HAS PROVEN HIMSELF
IN BATTLE.
PERHAPS HE SHOULD
RULE THE EMPIRE.
IF ARCHER FAILS, HIS CREW WILL
HAVE TO ANSWER FOR HIS CRIMES.
WE'LL BE EXECUTED.
THERE'S AN OLD TRADITION.
IF SOMEONE SAVES
THE EMPEROR'S LIFE,
IT'S SAID THERE'S NO REQUEST
HE CAN REFUSE HIM.
CONSIDER THE POSSIBILITIES.
A MEDICAL FACILITY OF YOUR OWN
WITH UNLIMITED RESOURCES.
YOU COULD CONDUCT EXPERIMENTS
AS YOU SEE FIT.
DON'T FORGET THE FEMALES.
FEMALES?
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO CHOOSE AS
MANY CONCUBINES AS YOU'D LIKE.
IF THE EMPEROR
WERE MY PATIENT,
I'D BE OBLIGATED
TO SAVE HIS LIFE.
I SUPPOSE WHAT YOU'RE SUGGESTING
ISN'T THAT DIFFERENT.
-WHAT'S THIS?
-SAVE IT, COMMANDER.
THE SCHEMATICS YOU DOWNLOADED,
WHERE ARE THEY?
SCHEMATICS?
LET'S GO.
[ GRUNTING ]
I WAS HOPING
YOU'D PUT UP A FIGHT.
YAAH! I'M SURPRISED
YOU'RE NOT EXHAUSTED
FROM ALL THE BEDS
YOU'VE JUMPED INTO RECENTLY.
[ GRUNTING ]
COMMANDER TUCKER TOLD ME
I SHOULD GIVE YOU
A FEW POINTERS IN THAT AREA.
-[ GUN FIRES ]
-AAAH!
[ PANTING ]
BRING HER.
SHUT DOWN THE TURBOLIFTS.
SECURE THE BRIDGE.
[ LAUGHS ]
WHO ARE YOU WORKING WITH?
I HOPE YOU'RE
PREPARED TO DIE.
MY DEATH WILL CHANGE NOTHING.
YOU WILL NOT PREVAIL.
THE DEFIANT WILL PREVAIL.
IT'S SIMPLY A MATTER
OF FIREPOWER.
THE FEDERATION IS OUR FUTURE.
YOU'RE MISTAKING OUR UNIVERSE
FOR SOMEONE ELSE'S.
IT MAY TAKE CENTURIES,
BUT HUMANITY WILL PAY
FOR ITS ARROGANCE.
[ COMMUNICATOR BEEPING ]
THESE INTERRUPTIONS
AREN'T HELPING.
-I need an estimate.
-THE INSIDE OF THIS PANEL
doesn't look anything like
the schematic you gave me.
YOU NEED TO REMOVE
THE DUOTRONIC MODULE.
The relays are behind it.
I'VE REMOVED THE MODULE.
YOU HAVE TO DISENGAGE
THE FLOW REGULATORS
BEFORE YOU REMOVE THE RELAYS
or the plasma will ignite.
[ BEEPING ]
SOMEONE'S TRYING TO OVERRIDE
THE BRIDGE LOCKOUTS.
DOCTOR, YOU MUST HURRY.
THE WARP FIELD'S FLUCTUATING.
IT'S A POWER DRAIN.
PRIMARY E.P.S. RELAYS.
-I'LL ALERT THE CAPTAIN.
-NO.
PROBABLY JUST A MICRO-FRACTURE
IN THE CONDUIT.
DO YOU REALLY WANT TO INTERRUPT
THE CAPTAIN FOR THAT?
I'LL HANDLE IT. TAKE OVER.
YES, SIR.
TAKE A TEAM ABOARD AVENGER.
CONFINE EVERY ALIEN
ON THAT SHIP.
THERE IS NO POINT
IN CONTINUING.
SHE'S NOT GOING TO TALK.
WE SHOULD KILL HER.
YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING FORWARD TO
THAT FOR A WHILE, HAVEN'T YOU?
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ ALARM BLARING ]
ARCHER TO THE BRIDGE! REPORT!
Main power's offline.
We've dropped out of warp.
CLOSE TO 10,000 METERS.
TARGET THEIR PRIMARY HULL.
PHLOX TO SOVAL,
I'M FINISHED HERE.
STAND BY TO TRANSPORT --
[ GASPS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
WHAT THE HELL HAVE YOU DONE?
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
[ BEEPING ]
I NEED WEAPONS!
EVERYTHING'S OFFLINE.
[ GRUNTS ]
CONTINUE FIRING.
[ GROANS ]
[ BEEPING ]
PRIMARY SYSTEMS
ARE COMING BACK.
WE HAVE SHIELDS.
-RAISE THEM.
-SOVAL TO PHLOX.
Their power grid's
being restored.
What's happening?
Doctor? Respond!
WEAPONS ARE ONLINE.
DESTROY THEM!
GET US OUT
OF THEIR WEAPONS' RANGE!
DIVERT ALL POWER
TO HULL PLATING.
THEY'VE TAKEN HEAVY DAMAGE.
THEY'RE TRYING TO ESCAPE.
PHOTON TORPEDOES.
LOCK ON TO THEIR REACTOR.
AAAAH!
[ SIGHS ]
[ GROANS ]
BEFORE I FORGET,
FIRST THING TOMORROW,
I WANT YOU TO ERASE
THE HISTORICAL DATABASE.
[ SIGHS ]
I DON'T WANT ANYONE ELSE
GETTING ANY IDEAS
ABOUT THIS FEDERATION
OF PLANETS.
WE'LL LOSE ALL THE DATA
ON OUR COUNTERPARTS.
EXACTLY.
IT'LL ONLY TAKE A DAY FOR
THE FLEET TO RETURN TO EARTH.
DO YOU THINK THE COMMANDERS
WILL SUPPORT YOU?
THEY'RE LOYAL TO THE EMPEROR.
THEY DON'T REALLY CARE
WHO IT IS.
BY THE TIME THE FLEET ARRIVES,
THE REIGN OF
EMPEROR JONATHAN ARCHER
WILL HAVE ALREADY BEGUN.
[ CHUCKLING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
ONCE WE'VE PUT DOWN
THE REBELLION,
I'LL EXPAND
THE EMPIRE THROUGHOUT...
THROUGHOUT...
[ GROANS ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[ DOOR OPENING ]
[ GASPS ]
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO FLEET ADMIRAL GARDNER.
CHANNEL OPEN.
THIS IS THE STARSHIP DEFIANT.
IF YOU DON'T
SURRENDER IMMEDIATELY,
WE'LL BEGIN TARGETING
YOUR CITIES. RESPOND.
WHERE'S ARCHER?
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
YOU'RE SPEAKING
WITH EMPRESS SATO.
PREPARE TO RECEIVE
INSTRUCTIONS.