HOW SERIOUS?
IF THE SWELLING GETS WORSE,
IT COULD INHIBIT HER BREATHING.
I TOLD YOU TO NOTIFY ME
IF THERE WAS ANY TROUBLE.
NOW, YOU SAY THIS HAS BEEN
GOING ON FOR DAYS?
THE MONITORING EQUIPMENT
DIDN'T DETECT THE SYMPTOMS
UNTIL THIS MORNING.
IT ISN'T CALIBRATED
FOR THIS TYPE OF PATIENT.
WELL?
FEVER'S DIMINISHED.
SHE'S FIGHTING IT OFF.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS...
FOR BOTH OF YOU.
INTRAVASCULAR PRESSURE
HAS STABILIZED.
BLOOD OXYGENATION IS GOOD.
SHE LOOKS SO INNOCENT.
IT'S ALMOST POSSIBLE
TO FORGET WHAT SHE REPRESENTS.
WE DON'T
WANT TO DISTURB HER.
[ SIGHS ]
NO.
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG ROAD ♪
♪ GETTING FROM THERE TO HERE ♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME ♪
♪ BUT MY TIME IS FINALLY NEAR ♪
♪ AND I WILL SEE MY DREAM
COME ALIVE AT LAST ♪
♪ I WILL TOUCH THE SKY ♪
♪ AND THEY'RE NOT GONNA
HOLD ME DOWN NO MORE ♪
♪ NO, THEY'RE NOT GONNA
CHANGE MY MIND ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ OF THE HEART ♪
♪ I'M GOING WHERE MY HEART
WILL TAKE ME ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ I CAN DO ANYTHING ♪
♪ I'VE GOT STRENGTH
OF THE SOUL ♪
♪ AND NO ONE'S GONNA BEND
OR BREAK ME ♪
♪ I CAN REACH ANY STAR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ I'VE GOT, I'VE GOT,
I'VE GOT ♪
♪ I'VE GOT FAITH ♪
♪ FAITH OF THE HEART ♪
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG,
JANUARY 19, 2155.
ENTERPRISE HAS BEEN CALLED HOME
FOR WHAT COULD PROVE
TO BE A PIVOTAL MOMENT
IN HUMAN HISTORY.
HAVING ENDURED
A CATASTROPHIC WORLD WAR,
EARTH'S GOVERNMENTS
CAME TO THIS CITY
FOR THE PURPOSE OF CREATING
A JUST AND LASTING PEACE
AMONG NATIONS.
TODAY, WE HAVE
ASSEMBLED HERE AGAIN,
REPRESENTATIVES
OF NUMEROUS WORLDS,
TO FORGE
AN UNPRECEDENTED ALLIANCE.
WITH THIS COALITION
OF PLANETS,
WE SEEK TO STRENGTHEN
OUR BONDS OF FRIENDSHIP,
RENDER PERMANENT THE PEACE
THAT NOW EXISTS AMONG US
FOR THE ONGOING EXPLORATION
OF OUR GALAXY.
LET US DEDICATE OURSELVES
TO THESE WORTHY GOALS
SO THAT FUTURE GENERATIONS
CAN LOOK BACK UPON THIS MOMENT
WITH PRIDE AND ETERNAL
GRATITUDE. THANK YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
PEOPLE ARE WATCHING.
NOBODY KNOWS THAT
BETTER THAN HIM.
CLAP LOUDER.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
AH. I THOUGHT
IT WAS A FINE SPEECH.
JUST MISSING A FEW NAMES.
YOU'D THINK
THIS WAS ALL HIS IDEA.
IT'S NOT ABOUT
WHO GETS CREDIT.
HE COULD HAVE AT LEAST
MENTIONED ENTERPRISE.
WHO DOES HE THINK
GOT THE ANDORIANS
AND TELLARITES TALKING?
I'M SURE HISTORY
WILL REFLECT OUR CONTRIBUTION.
NOT IF HE'S WRITING IT.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
I HOPE I DIDN'T EMBARRASS
MYSELF TOO MUCH.
FAR FROM IT, MINISTER.
CALL ME NATHAN.
I WANT TO THANK YOU AGAIN
FOR ATTENDING.
HAVING ENTERPRISE HERE
SEEMS TO PUT EVERYONE AT EASE.
PEOPLE FEEL COMFORTABLE
IN THE PRESENCE OF HEROES.
WHATEVER WE CAN DO
TO HELP.
WELL, IT CERTAINLY HELPS
THAT THE DELEGATES
CAN UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER.
THESE UNIVERSAL TRANSLATORS
WORK PERFECTLY, THANKS TO YOU.
I JUST UPDATED THEM
WITH A FEW THINGS
WE PICKED UP ON THE MISSION.
WHATEVER YOU DID,
THEY'RE EXTREMELY PRECISE.
THOUGH, WHEN I'M LISTENING
TO THE TELLARITE AMBASSADOR,
I WISH THEY WERE JUST
A LITTLE LESS PRECISE.
YOU'VE SET
A FORMIDABLE GOAL.
THE DRAFTING OF A CHARTER
IN SIX WEEKS?
I'VE ALWAYS BELIEVED
THAT FORMIDABLE GOALS
PRODUCE FORMIDABLE RESULTS.
I DECIDED TO STOP WAITING.
FOR WHAT?
YOU TO COME OVER
AND SAY HELLO.
YOU WERE BUSY WORKING.
WE NEVER HAD A PROBLEM MIXING
WORK AND PLEASURE.
SMILE.
I NEVER COULD GET YOU
TO SMILE FOR THE CAMERA.
HOW HAVE YOU BEEN, GANNET?
BUSY.
THERE HAVEN'T BEEN
MANY SLOW NEWS DAYS
SINCE THE XINDI ATTACK.
I HEAR YOU'RE GONNA BE
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD A WHILE?
AT LEAST UNTIL
THE CONFERENCE IS OVER.
WE SHOULD GET TOGETHER.
IF WE WAIT ANOTHER FOUR YEARS,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TOO MUCH CATCHING UP TO DO.
CAN'T ARGUE WITH THAT.
I'LL PRETEND THAT WAS
AN ENTHUSIASTIC "YES."
BACK TO WORK.
COMMANDER TUCKER
DOES HAVE A POINT.
ENTERPRISE LAID
THE FOUNDATION FOR THIS EVENT.
PERHAPS IT SHOULD BE YOU
THEY'RE PHOTOGRAPHING.
SAMUELS LIKES THE SPOTLIGHT,
AND HE'S WELCOME TO IT.
[ GASPING ]
THEY'RE GOING TO KILL HER.
EXCUSE ME?
DON'T LET THEM.
[ GASPING ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
I'M SORRY.
-IT'S A PHASE-PISTOL WOUND.
-SHE'S GOING INTO SHOCK.
GET ME A MED KIT!
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I JUST RECEIVED WORD
FROM STARFLEET MEDICAL.
THE WOUND WAS TOO SEVERE.
SHE DIDN'T SURVIVE.
DO THEY THINK IT COULD
HAVE BEEN SELF-INFLICTED?
THEY DIDN'T SAY.
DO WE KNOW WHO SHE WAS?
HER NAME WAS SUSAN KHOURI.
SHE WAS A MEDICAL TECHNICIAN.
SHE'D BEEN HAVING
SOME EMOTIONAL TROUBLE.
TOOK A LEAVE FROM WORK
OVER A YEAR AGO.
ANY IDEA
WHO THE HAIR BELONGED TO?
I HAVE A VERY GOOD IDEA.
IT WAS FROM A CHILD
NO MORE THAN 6 MONTHS OLD.
I USED EVERY DNA IDENTIFICATION
PROTOCOL I'M AWARE OF.
I EVEN USED
A KLINGON PROCEDURE.
GO AHEAD.
IT CONTAINS VULCAN
AND HUMAN DNA.
I HAD THE COMPUTER SEARCH
FOR ANY MATCHES
IN THE STARFLEET DATABANK.
WHEN I GOT THE RESULTS,
I RAN THE SEARCH THREE MORE
TIMES, JUST TO BE CERTAIN.
AND?
ACCORDING TO EVERY ANALYSIS,
THIS CHILD IS THE OFFSPRING
OF COMMANDER TUCKER
AND COMMANDER T'POL.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
COME IN.
WE GOT TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
IT'S DIFFICULT
TO TALK ABOUT SOMETHING
THAT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
PHLOX SAID DNA DOESN'T LIE.
NEITHER DO I.
I'VE NEVER BEEN PREGNANT,
TRIP.
THEN HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
ALL OF THIS?
I CAN'T.
DO YOU BELIEVE ME?
YEAH.
PHLOX MUST BE WRONG,
THAT'S ALL THERE IS TO IT.
IF YOU'VE NEVER BEEN PREGNANT,
THEN YOU CAN'T HAVE A BABY.
TRIP, THE MOMENT PHLOX
SAID THAT THE CHILD WAS OURS,
I KNEW IT WAS TRUE.
-BUT YOU SAID YOU'D NEVER BEEN--
-I HAVEN'T.
THEN WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
I CAN'T EXPLAIN HOW IT EXISTS,
BUT I KNOW IT DOES.
THERE'S A CHILD OUT THERE,
AND IT'S OURS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
I'M VULCAN.
FORTUNATELY,
THE NEWS HASN'T SPREAD
TO THE GENERAL PUBLIC.
AND I'D LIKE
TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
IF WE MADE AN ANNOUNCEMENT,
SOMEONE MIGHT COME FORWARD
WITH INFORMATION.
AN ANNOUNCEMENT OF THIS NATURE
COULD DERAIL THE CONFERENCE.
HOW?
YOU HAVEN'T SPENT
MUCH TIME ON EARTH LATELY.
AFTER THE XINDI ATTACK,
THERE WAS A DANGEROUS
INCREASE IN XENOPHOBIA.
WE GOT A TASTE OF IT.
IT DIED DOWN SOMEWHAT,
BUT NOT COMPLETELY.
THERE ARE STILL PEOPLE OUT THERE
WHO WANT US TO STAY
IN OUR LITTLE CORNER
OF THE GALAXY.
THE NEWS OF
A VULCAN-HUMAN HYBRID
COULD INFLAME THEM, GIVE THEM
SOMETHING TO RALLY AGAINST.
I CAN'T BELIEVE WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT
MORE THAN A SMALL
MINORITY.
AS I SAID, YOU'VE BEEN
AWAY FOR A WHILE.
MAYBE I JUST HAVE A LITTLE MORE
FAITH IN HUMANITY THAN YOU DO.
CAN'T AFFORD
TO OPERATE ON FAITH.
THERE'S MORE AT STAKE HERE
THAN A SIMPLE TRADE AGREEMENT.
YOU FOUGHT THE XINDI.
YOU KNOW BETTER THAN ANYONE
HOW EARTH'S SURVIVAL DEPENDS
ON ALLIANCES WITH OTHER SPECIES.
WE DON'T HAVE THE VULCANS
WATCHING OUR BACKS ANYMORE.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT FINDING
SOMEONE ELSE TO WATCH OUR BACKS.
ALL I'M SAYING IS THAT
THERE'S STRENGTH IN NUMBERS.
ALL RIGHT.
[ SIGHS ]
I WAS HOPING YOU'D HAVE
SOME WORD ON THE INVESTIGATION.
MY ENGINEER AND SCIENCE OFFICER
ARE EAGER TO GET SOME ANSWERS.
OH, I'M SURE THEY ARE,
BUT I'VE HEARD NOTHING NEW.
THERE'S GOT TO BE SOMETHING
WE CAN DO.
STARFLEET INVESTIGATORS ARE MORE
THAN CAPABLE OF HANDLING THIS.
I SUGGEST WE LET THEM
DO THEIR JOB.
I'LL NOTIFY YOU
THE MOMENT I HEAR SOMETHING.
I APPRECIATE
YOUR COOPERATION.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ BEEPS ]
-Reed.
-IT'S CAPTAIN ARCHER.
I WANT YOU TO TALK
TO AN OLD FRIEND.
THE LAST TIME WE SPOKE,
YOU ASKED ME TO NEVER
CONTACT YOU AGAIN.
I CONTACTED YOU.
SUSAN KHOURI.
-FIRST, WE NEED
AN UNDERSTANDING.
-ABOUT WHAT?
THAT BY SPEAKING TO ME,
YOU'RE BACK IN THE GAME.
-SIMPLE AS THAT.
-WHO WAS SHE?
SHE WAS MORE THAN JUST
AN EMOTIONALLY TROUBLED NURSE.
SHE WAS A MEMBER
OF AN UNDERGROUND ISOLATIONIST
MOVEMENT -- TERRA PRIME.
I'VE HEARD OF THEM.
THEY WANT TO STOP ALL CONTACT
WITH ALIEN SPECIES.
THEY BELIEVE IT'S CORRUPTING
OUR WAY OF LIFE.
THEY MADE A LOT OF NOISE
WHEN ENTERPRISE WAS LAUNCHED.
THEY HAD A RESURGENCE
FOLLOWING THE XINDI ATTACK.
WE THINK KHOURI WAS TRYING
TO LEAVE THE MOVEMENT.
THAT'S WHY THEY KILLED HER?
HER DEFECTION MAY HAVE HAD
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THE CHILD.
I WAS GETTING TO THAT.
THE CHILD BELONGS TO TWO
OF YOUR CREWMEN. YOU TELL ME.
THEY CLAIM THEY KNOW
NOTHING ABOUT IT.
THAT DOESN'T SEEM LIKELY,
DOES IT?
I BELIEVE THEM.
I ADMIRE YOUR LOYALTY.
WE THINK TERRA PRIME
IS INVOLVED,
THAT THEY'RE
PLANNING SOMETHING.
YOU JUST DON'T KNOW WHAT?
WE SUSPECT IT HAS SOMETHING
TO DO WITH THE CHILD.
FIND IT,
YOU'LL HAVE THE ANSWERS.
YOU RECRUITED HER.
I NEEDED HER EXPERTISE.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS RELIABLE.
OBVIOUSLY YOU WERE MISTAKEN.
IF SHE'D TOLD THEM ANYTHING
TRULY DAMAGING, I THINK
WE'D KNOW IT BY NOW.
WE CAN'T BE SURE
WHAT SHE TOLD THEM.
ANYWAY, I'M MORE CONCERNED WITH
WHY SHE TURNED AWAY FROM US.
I THINK THAT SHE MIGHT HAVE
BECOME ATTACHED TO THE PATIENT.
SHE SPENT A GREAT DEAL OF TIME
CARING FOR HER.
-AND WHAT ABOUT YOU?
-ME?
YES. YOU'VE SPENT AS MUCH TIME
WITH THE CHILD AS SHE DID.
I FEEL NO DIFFERENTLY ABOUT IT
THAN ANYONE ELSE
THAT I'VE TREATED.
THIS ISN'T "ANYONE ELSE."
THIS IS AN ABOMINATION.
AND WHEN THE TIME COMES,
IT WILL BE TREATED AS SUCH.
I UNDERSTAND.
WELL, I'M GONNA
MISS THIS PLACE.
THE SIMPLICITY.
THERE'S NO MIDDLE GROUND HERE.
AND I CAN SEE THE EARTH.
SEND IN GREAVES
ON YOUR WAY OUT.
YES, SIR.
I GAVE THE MEN
YOUR MESSAGE.
WE'LL BE READY
AT A MOMENT'S NOTICE.
TELL THEM I APPRECIATE
THEIR HARD WORK.
-THEY ALREADY KNOW.
-THERE'S ONE OTHER THING.
A LOOSE END THAT NEEDS TYING UP.
PUT TOGETHER A GROUP, HAVE THEM
MEET ME AT THE THIRD JUNCTION,
SAY, ONE HOUR.
DONE.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
THE TELLARITES ARE PUSHING FOR
AN EMBARGO AGAINST THE ORIONS.
THEY CLAIM THEY'VE BEEN
ATTACKING THEIR FREIGHTERS.
WE'VE TRADED WITH THE ORIONS
FOR CENTURIES.
WE WOULD HAVE KNOWN
OF THESE ATTACKS.
IT'S TELLARITE SLANDER.
YOU HAVE TO APPRECIATE
THEIR POINT OF VIEW.
THE TELLARITES ONLY WANT TO
DEPRIVE US OF VALUABLE COMMERCE.
CORIDAN WILL NEVER AGREE
TO ANY TRADE SANCTIONS.
AMBASSADOR, CAPTAIN ARCHER.
AMBASSADOR.
I NEED TO CONTACT MY GOVERNMENT
ABOUT TODAY'S DEVELOPMENTS.
EXCUSE ME.
[ SIGHING ]
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
I WANT EVERYTHING STARFLEET HAS
ON THE INVESTIGATION.
WHY COME TO ME?
BECAUSE THE CHIEF INVESTIGATOR
TURNED ME DOWN.
YOU CAN CHANGE HIS MIND.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
I'M SORRY.
SUSAN KHOURI
WAS A MEMBER OF TERRA PRIME.
IF THAT'S TRUE,
IT'S EXTREMELY TROUBLING.
NOT AS TROUBLING
AS SOMETHING ELSE WE LEARNED.
YOU WERE ONCE A MEMBER.
IT SEEMS YOU'RE DOING FAIRLY
WELL INVESTIGATING ON YOUR OWN.
THAT'S WHY
YOU WANTED THIS KEPT QUIET.
I'VE ALREADY EXPLAINED WHY
THERE WAS A NEED FOR SECRECY.
I WAS VERY YOUNG
WHEN I JOINED TERRA PRIME.
YOU WERE 18.
DIDN'T YOU MAKE
ANY QUESTIONABLE CHOICES
WHEN YOU WERE THAT AGE,
CAPTAIN?
IT WAS A STUPID MISTAKE.
I WAS A FOOL.
MY FATHER HAD DIED
IN A FREIGHTER ACCIDENT,
AND I BLAMED THE PILOT,
WHO HAPPENED TO BE DENOBULAN.
WE ALL HAVE OUR DEMONS.
I'VE EXORCISED MINE.
I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU DID
WHEN YOU WERE YOUNG, MINISTER.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
[ SCOFFS ]
I UNDERESTIMATED YOU.
I SUPPOSE I'M NOT
THE FIRST PERSON
TO MAKE THAT MISTAKE.
YOU'LL HAVE YOUR
CASE FILE WITHIN THE HOUR.
THANK YOU.
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
HMM. CAN'T DECIDE -- IF I LIKE
YOU BETTER IN UNIFORM OR NOT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I'VE BEEN ASSIGNED TO DO
A STORY ON ENTERPRISE.
HM. THEY CAN BUILD A SHIP
THAT GOES FASTER THAN LIGHT,
-BUT THEY CAN'T GIVE
YOU A DECENT-SIZED ROOM.
-A STORY?
IT'S TOLD FROM THE PERSPECTIVE
OF THE CREW.
IT'LL COVER THE MISSIONS,
THE PERILS, LIFE IN SPACE.
SO, SHALL WE START
WITH A TOUR?
-I'VE GOT SOME WORK TO DO.
-YOU'RE NOT ON DUTY.
GANNET.
OKAY, SO...
[ SIGHS ]
MAYBE...
I WASN'T ASSIGNED THE STORY.
MAYBE I SUGGESTED THE IDEA
TO MY EDITOR.
HE KNOW HOW YOU FEEL
ABOUT SPACE EXPLORATION?
THAT IT'S THE "LAST VESTIGE
OF COLONIAL IMPULSE"?
I ONLY SAID THAT TO KEEP YOU
FROM SIGNING ON TO THIS MISSION.
FIND ANOTHER STORY TO DO.
IT'S TOO LATE.
IT'S DUE A WEEK FROM TODAY.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO FIND ANOTHER SOURCE
FOR YOUR INFORMATION.
WHY ARE YOU AVOIDING ME?
CAN YOU GIVE ME ONE REASON
WHY I SHOULDN'T AVOID YOU?
WE BOTH CALLED IT OFF.
IT WAS A MUTUAL DECISION.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'VE CHANGED YOUR MIND.
I HAVEN'T DECIDED YET.
THAT'S THE FIRST
HONEST THING YOU'VE SAID.
SO, REWARD ME
BY GIVING ME THAT TOUR.
GOT A MINUTE?
CERTAINLY.
[ SIGHS ]
THIS BABY...
CAN YOU TELL
IF IT'S A BOY OR A GIRL?
IT'S A GIRL.
A GIRL.
IS IT OKAY? I MEAN,
PART HUMAN AND PART VULCAN.
VULCAN AND HUMAN PHYSIOLOGY
ARE NOT ALL THAT DISSIMILAR.
FROM THE EVIDENCE I HAVE,
THERE'S NO REASON TO BELIEVE
SHE'S ANYTHING
BUT PERFECTLY HEALTHY.
THAT'S GOOD TO HEAR.
YOU'LL ALSO BE INTERESTED
TO KNOW SHE HAS YOUR EYES,
AND T'POL'S EARS.
I-I-I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I'M IN SOMETHING OF A QUANDARY
ABOUT IT MYSELF,
ESPECIALLY SINCE T'POL'S
NEVER BEEN PREGNANT.
SHE COULD HAVE GOTTEN PREGNANT
AND NOT TOLD ME ABOUT IT.
AH.
AND SHE HAD THE EMBRYO REMOVED,
ALSO WITHOUT YOUR KNOWLEDGE?
I BELIEVE YOU KNOW THE ANSWER
TO THAT THEORY, COMMANDER.
YEAH, I GUESS I DO.
WE'LL GET TO THE BOTTOM
OF THIS SOON ENOUGH.
UNTIL THEN, I SUGGEST YOU KEEP
ANY SUCH THEORIES TO YOURSELF.
THAT'S GOOD ADVICE.
YOU KNOW, MY FATHER
ALWAYS WANTED A GRANDDAUGHTER.
HE BUGGED MY SISTER
ABOUT IT CONSTANTLY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
IT SEEMS HE GOT HIS WISH.
WHEW.
[ AUDIENCE APPLAUDING ]
IN THE SHADOW OF THIS
INCALCULABLE DEVASTATION,
WE FIND OURSELVES FACING
A COLOSSAL CHALLENGE.
THERE'S AN ENTIRE WORLD
TO REBUILD.
NOT ONLY OUR CITIES AND HOMES,
BUT MANKIND ITSELF!
NOW IS NOT THE TIME FOR
TIMIDITY AND SECOND-GUESSING.
WE CANNOT AFFORD
TO DOUBT OURSELVES.
THE THIRD WORLD WAR
HAD JUST ENDED,
AND THE CEASE-FIRE
WAS BARELY 2 YEARS OLD.
UNLESS WE ACT DECISIVELY,
WE WILL PASS ON THE SCARS
OF MUTATION AND DECAY
TO FUTURE GENERATIONS.
-COLONEL GREEN.
ONE OF THE MANY MEN
HISTORY HAS MISUNDERSTOOD.
FOR THE SAKE OF OUR CHILDREN
AND OUR CHILDREN'S CHILDREN,
WE MUST REJECT THE IMPURE
AND CAST IT OUT!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ BEEPS ]
BEFORE MY FATHER DIED
AND LEFT ME THIS FACILITY,
I WAS STUDYING
TO BE AN HISTORIAN.
UNTIL I HAD
A VERY VERBAL CONFRONTATION
WITH A CERTAIN PROFESSOR
WHO CLAIMED THAT GREEN
WAS NOTHING MORE
THAN A GENOCIDAL MADMAN.
SOUNDS LIKE WE HAD
THE SAME PROFESSOR.
GREEN EUTHANIZED
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
WHO WERE AFFLICTED
WITH RADIATION DAMAGE.
THEIR MILLIONS OF DESCENDANTS
WOULD HAVE ENDURED
HORRIBLE DISEASE,
YET HISTORY --
HISTORY NEVER SAYS ANYTHING
ABOUT THAT SUFFERING
THAT GREEN PREVENTED.
GUESS IT ALL DEPENDS
ON WHO WRITES THE HISTORY.
MAKES ME WONDER
IF I'LL BE REMEMBERED
WITH ANY MORE ACCURACY.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE
GOING TO BE MISUNDERSTOOD.
REALLY? SOMETIMES I'M NOT
CERTAIN I UNDERSTAND MYSELF.
WE DID WHAT WE HAD TO DO,
NOT WHAT WE WANTED TO DO.
I'M SURE GREEN
TOLD HIMSELF THE SAME THING.
HE WAS RIGHT, AND SO ARE WE.
DANIEL, YOU ARE A...
WISE MAN.
MEDICAL REPORT ON THE PATIENT.
HER SYMPTOMS ARE GONE.
SHE'S 100%.
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
WONDERFUL. THANK YOU.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
THAT WAS SOME SERIOUS FLYING,
TRYING TO KEEP
THE WARP FIELDS ALIGNED.
COLUMBIA WAS 50 METERS
ABOVE US.
ONE WRONG MOVE, AND WE WOULD
HAVE LOST COMMANDER TUCKER.
HOW DID YOU KEEP YOUR COOL?
WHEN I WAS STUDYING
TO BE A PILOT,
I MEMORIZED SOMETHING
CHUCK YEAGER SAID --
"I NEVER LET MYSELF BE AFRAID.
I JUST FOCUS ON THE DIALS
AND CONCENTRATE ON FLYING."
-THAT SIMPLE, HUH?
-MOST OF THE TIME,
SIMPLE WORKS BEST.
THESE ARE THE SHUTTLEPODS.
WHICH ONE DID YOU USE
TO PENETRATE THE SPHERE
IN THE EXPANSE?
SHUTTLEPOD 1.
YOU WANT TO SEE INSIDE?
IF IT'S OKAY.
OHH!
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE SHIP.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT SO.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE USE
THE SHUTTLEPODS LESS AND LESS.
WHY?
WE'RE GETTING MORE COMFORTABLE
WITH THE TRANSPORTER.
MAKES SENSE. GETS YOU THERE
IN A FEW SECONDS.
YEAH, BUT THERE'S
NO SKILL INVOLVED.
MM-HMM.
NOTHING TO FLY.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD A TENDENCY
TO GET ATTACHED TO MACHINES.
IT'S CRAZY, BUT EVERY TIME
WE USE THE TRANSPORTER,
I FEEL WE'RE KIND OF TURNING
OUR BACKS ON THESE GUYS.
YOU CAN'T MAKE A CHOICE WITHOUT
LEAVING SOMETHING BEHIND.
WHEN I SAW YOU
AT THAT CONFERENCE,
I STARTED THINKING
ABOUT THINGS,
DECISIONS I'VE MADE.
IS IT MY IMAGINATION,
OR ARE YOU ACTUALLY
OPENING UP TO ME?
-DON'T DO THAT.
-WHAT?
WHENEVER THINGS
GET A LITTLE SERIOUS,
YOU ALWAYS
TURN IT INTO A JOKE.
[ SIGHS ]
IT'S A BAD HABIT.
I HAVE A LOT OF THOSE.
HERE'S ANOTHER ONE.
WHEN I'M ATTRACTED TO SOMEONE,
I CAN'T HIDE IT FOR LONG.
YOU AND YOUR BAD HABITS.
THE AUTOPSY DATA CONFIRMS
WHAT WE ALREADY KNEW.
SUSAN KHOURI WAS KILLED
BY PHASE-PISTOL FIRE.
THE CASE FILE CONTAINS
VERY LITTLE ELSE
IN THE WAY OF EVIDENCE.
SOME BIOGRAPHICAL
DATA ON KHOURI.
MOST OF IT'S OUT OF DATE.
THEY DON'T EVEN KNOW WHERE SHE'D
BEEN LIVING FOR THE PAST YEAR.
IT'S LIKE SHE DROPPED
OFF THE FACE OF THE EARTH.
-THAT MAY BE
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
-YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
HER BLOOD HAD ELEVATED LEVELS
OF GROWTH HORMONE.
I RAN SOME MORE TESTS AND FOUND
TRACES OF MYOFIBRILIN.
THAT'S WHAT THEY PRESCRIBE
FOR EXTENDED ZERO-G MISSIONS.
IT'S HARDLY USED ANYMORE,
OUTSIDE OF MILITARY EXERCISES,
NOT SINCE THE INVENTION
OF ARTIFICIAL GRAVITY.
IT IS STILL GIVEN
TO WORKERS IN REMOTE PLACES
WHERE ARTIFICIAL GRAVITY
ISN'T PRACTICAL.
LIKE MINING COLONIES.
THE NEAREST ONE IS ORPHEUS,
ON THE MOON.
I HAVE HEARD THAT
THE MOON IS A HOTBED
OF TERRA PRIME ACTIVITY.
YOU KNOW, I THINK TRAVIS HAS
A FRIEND WHO WORKED ON ORPHEUS.
HE MIGHT BE ABLE TO GET
A COUPLE OF US INSIDE.
WE COULD PAY A LITTLE VISIT,
UNDERCOVER.
I WANT TO BE A PART
OF THAT VISIT.
I'D LIKE TO VOLUNTEER, AS WELL.
TELL TRAVIS
TO SEE WHAT HE CAN DO.
YES, SIR.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
CAPTAIN'S STARLOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
WITH HELP
FROM TRAVIS'S CONTACT,
TRIP AND T'POL
HAVE BEEN PROCESSED
INTO THE ORPHEUS
MINING FACILITY.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
THIS IS THE SECOND TIME
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH HERE.
I'VE SEEN ALL THIS BEFORE.
WE STILL HAVE 20 MINUTES
BEFORE WE HAVE TO REPORT
TO THE FOREMAN.
MAYBE YOU DOWNLOADED
AN OUTDATED MAP.
THE MAP IS CORRECT.
MAYBE YOU'RE
READING IT WRONG.
WE CAN ASK FOR DIRECTIONS.
GIVE ME THAT.
I THINK I KNOW
WHAT THE PROBLEM IS.
-WHAT?
-WE'RE LOST.
-LET'S TRY THAT DIRECTION.
-ANY PARTICULAR REASON?
IT'S THE ONLY TUNNEL
I DON'T RECOGNIZE.
TRIP...
I THINK WE'RE GETTING THERE.
I KNOW YOU'RE NOT CONVINCED
I'VE TOLD YOU THE TRUTH
-ABOUT THE CHILD.
-WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU THINK I MIGHT HAVE GOTTEN
PREGNANT WITHOUT YOUR KNOWLEDGE.
I NEVER SAID THAT.
I KNOW.
YOU'VE BEEN TALKING TO PHLOX.
NO. HAVE YOU?
LOOK, IT'S BECAUSE
YOU'RE VULCAN, ISN'T IT,
-THAT YOU KNOW ALL THIS?
-I BELIEVE SO.
I AM SICK AND TIRED
OF THIS BOND WE'VE GOT.
I DON'T PARTICULARLY
ENJOY IT, EITHER.
LISTEN, FOR THE LAST TIME,
AND FOR THE RECORD,
I DO BELIEVE YOU.
AND IF YOU GET ANY
MORE FEELINGS -- WHAT?
THERE IT IS.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
I'M GLAD WE FINALLY
LEFT THE SHUTTLEPOD.
I THOUGHT YOU LIKED SHUTTLEPODS.
I LIKE FLYING THEM.
HMM. SURE FELT
LIKE WE WERE FLYING.
I HAVE A RULE.
IF I'M IN BED WITH SOMEONE,
THEY HAVE TO BE IN BED WITH ME.
WHAT WAS THAT?
[ GRUNTS ]
AH.
YOU ARE NOT HERE.
I'M JUST WORRIED
ABOUT SOME FRIENDS OF MINE.
WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT?
I'M UNDER ORDERS NOT
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
THAT'S THE LAST THING
YOU SHOULD TELL A REPORTER.
LET'S CHANGE THE SUBJECT.
HOW COME YOU HAVEN'T
SETTLED DOWN?
I'M NEVER GONNA SETTLE DOWN.
IT DOESN'T MEAN I'M NOT GONNA
GET SERIOUS WITH SOMEONE...
IF THE RIGHT CIRCUMSTANCE
COMES ALONG.
AND WHAT CONSTITUTES
THE RIGHT CIRCUMSTANCE?
I'LL KNOW IT WHEN IT HAPPENS.
WHAT DID YOU MEAN EARLIER
ABOUT RECONSIDERING
SOME DECISIONS YOU'VE MADE?
I'VE SPENT
MY WHOLE LIFE IN SPACE,
GOING FROM ONE PLACE
TO THE NEXT.
SEEING YOU,
I WAS WONDERING,
MAYBE THE NEXT CHALLENGE,
AT LEAST FOR ME,
IS TO STAY IN ONE PLACE
FOR A WHILE.
-HOSHI.
-HMM?
NO WORD YET
FROM TRIP OR T'POL.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN HELP WITH?
SIX OF THE UNIVERSAL TRANSLATORS
STARTED CONFUSING
RIGELIAN WITH ANDORIAN.
THERE'S A GLITCH SOMEWHERE,
BUT I CAN'T FIND IT.
CARRY ON.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
FRESH OFF THE BOAT?
ONE OF THE S.K. MODELS.
THEY ONLY GIVE THEM
TO GRUBBERS.
I GUESS YOU FOUND ME OUT.
[ LAUGHS ]
JOSIAH.
TURNER.
WHAT BRINGS YOU
TO THIS DUMP SITE?
CHANGE OF SCENERY.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
I WAS AFTER, TOO,
ONLY IT WASN'T
THE LANDSCAPE I GOT SICK OF.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
AT LEAST THERE AREN'T
AS MANY OF THEM UP HERE.
SEEMS LIKE EVERYWHERE YOU GO,
HUMANS ARE GETTING
TO BE AN ENDANGERED SPECIES.
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
BAD ENOUGH YOU CAN'T
WALK DOWN THE STREET
WITHOUT SOME FREAK SHOW SCARING
THE HELL OUT OF YOUR KIDS.
NOW THE GOVERNMENT'S
MAKING TREATIES WITH THEM.
SOMETIMES I WONDER
WHERE IT'S ALL GONNA END.
IT'S GONNA END WITH HUMAN BEINGS
BECOMING SECOND-CLASS CITIZENS
ON THEIR OWN WORLD.
SOMEONE'S GOT TO MAKE A STAND.
YEAH,
THAT'S HOW I FEEL, TOO.
SOME OF US ARE MEETING
TONIGHT AT 2200.
LEVEL 7, JUNCTION 4.
I THINK YOU'LL LIKE
WHAT WE HAVE TO SAY.
I'LL -- I'LL TRY AND MAKE IT.
I'LL LOOK FOR YOU.
I'VE LEARNED SOMETHING.
ONE OF THE LOCALS
ISN'T VERY FOND OF VULCANS.
YOU WERE SAYING?
A DOCTOR FROM ONE
OF THE MEDICAL FACILITIES
WAS FOUND DEAD YESTERDAY.
-THEY THINK IT WAS A CAVE-IN.
-YOU'RE NOT BUYING IT?
HE WORKED AT THE SAME CLINIC
AS SUSAN KHOURI.
I THINK WE EACH KNOW
WHAT WE'RE DOING TONIGHT.
7 MILLION PEOPLE
WIPED OUT BY ALIENS.
-DID THE XINDI EVEN APOLOGIZE?
-NO!
-DID OUR GOVERNMENT
EVER DEMAND AN APOLOGY?
-NO!
AND WHERE ARE THE REPARATIONS
FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THOSE 7 MILLION?
AND NOW THOSE SAME LEADERS
WANT TO FORM A COALITION
WITH TELLARITES, ANDORIANS,
RIGELIANS, CORIDANITES,
AND VULCANS!
VULCANS, WHO NOT TOO LONG AGO
MASSACRED 45 HUMANS
WORKING AT THE EARTH EMBASSY.
NATHAN SAMUELS CLAIMS
THAT FUTURE GENERATIONS
WILL LOOK BACK ON THIS ERA
WITH PRIDE.
BUT IF THINGS KEEP GOING
THE WAY THEY'RE GOING,
THERE WON'T BE
ANY FUTURE GENERATIONS,
AT LEAST NOT HUMAN!
[ CROWD AGREEING ]
I LOVE HUMANITY TOO MUCH
TO SIT BY AND LET THAT HAPPEN.
[ ZIPPER OPENS ]
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S ESTIMATED
THAT THERE ARE AT LEAST
5,000 UNREGISTERED
ALIENS ON EARTH.
NOW, ANOTHER STUDY
PUTS THAT FIGURE AT 10,000.
THIS INSANITY
IS THE DIRECT RESULT
OF OUR GOVERNMENT'S POLICY
AND THE ENFORCERS
OF THAT POLICY -- STARFLEET!
[ CROWD SHOUTING ]
WE NEED TO SEND A MESSAGE
TO THE PEOPLE IN POWER.
AND THERE'S SOMEONE HERE TONIGHT
WHO IS GOING TO HELP US
DO JUST THAT.
COMMANDER TUCKER...
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ALL THAT STUFF I SAID
ABOUT LEAVING THE SHIP...
OF COURSE,
IT'S OFF THE RECORD.
WHILE YOU'RE ON DUTY, YOU MIND
IF I STAY HERE AND WORK A BIT?
[ DOOR CHIMES ]
I NEED TO SPEAK TO GANNET.
SOMETHING WRONG?
COME WITH US.
-WHERE?
-WHAT'S GOING ON?
SHE'S NOT HERE TO DO A STORY
ON ENTERPRISE, TRAVIS.
SHE IS A SPY
FOR TERRA PRIME.
[ GASPING ]
-ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
-I THINK SO.
-WHAT DID YOU DO TO HER?
-HEY, HEY.
NOT NEARLY ENOUGH.
IT'S NOT WORTH IT, ROMEO.
JULIET'S IN GOOD HANDS.
THE TWO STAR-CROSSED LOVERS.
I CAN'T HELP BUT WONDER
WHETHER YOUR LITTLE DRAMA
WILL END HAPPIER THAN THAT
FAMOUS DOUBLE-SUICIDE
IN THE MEDIEVAL TOMB.
-WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
-JOHN FREDERICK PAXTON.
-I RUN THIS FACILITY.
-NOT FOR LONG.
YOU'RE RIGHT, THERE,
COMMANDER.
MY MINING BUSINESS IS ABOUT
TO TAKE A TURN FOR THE WORSE.
DANIEL, GET STARTED.
YOU'RE BEHIND THIS.
BEHIND THIS? NO.
I LEAD THIS,
AND PROUDLY, TOO.
BEFORE YOU ASK,
YOUR CHILD IS SAFE AND SOUND,
FINALLY SLEEPING
THROUGH THE NIGHT.
I FORGOT HOW MUCH TROUBLE
A NEWBORN CAN BE.
-I WANT TO SEE HER.
-NO.
AND "NO" IS A WORD THAT
STARFLEET BETTER GET USED
TO HEARING FROM NOW ON.
BECAUSE UP UNTIL TODAY, IT'S
ALWAYS BEEN "YES," HASN'T IT?
"YES, YES, GO RIGHT AHEAD,
ROAM THE STARS.
"YES, INFORM
POTENTIALLY HOSTILE SPECIES
OF THE WHEREABOUTS OF EARTH.
"YES, ENTRUST THE ENTIRE FUTURE
OF OUR WORLD
"TO NON-HUMAN CREATURES
WHO DON'T EVEN FEEL LIKE WE DO.
"YES, PROMOTE THE TOTAL
DEGRADATION OF MANKIND
BY ENCOURAGING
ALIEN-HUMAN...RELATIONS."
WELL, "YES" IS A WORD
THAT ENDS HERE AND NOW.
I AM RETURNING EARTH
TO ITS RIGHTFUL OWNERS.
I AM GIVING EARTH
BACK TO HUMANITY,
BACK TO HUMAN BEINGS.
IT IS MY LIFE'S WORK.
IT'S WHAT I WAS BORN TO DO.
AND THERE IS NO ONE --
NOT AN ALIEN, NOT A HUMAN --
THAT WILL STOP ME
FROM ACHIEVING IT.
MY FATHER DESIGNED
THIS FACILITY.
HE KNEW THAT MINING
WAS UNPREDICTABLE BUSINESS.
MINES TAP OUT.
VEINS DRY UP.
EVERYONE'S ABOARD, SIR.
GO TO LAUNCH MODE, DANIEL.
YOU'RE AN ENGINEER.
I THINK YOU'LL
APPRECIATE THIS.
[ RUMBLING ]
-TAKE A GOOD LONG LOOK.
-WHERE ARE WE GOING?
FOR YOU, THIS WILL BE LIKE
A WALK ACROSS THE STREET.
[ BEEPING ]
LOCK IT UP.
YOU BETTER HANG ON TO SOMETHING.
SHE GETS A LITTLE RUSTY
OUT OF THE GATE.
YOU RECONFIGURED
YOUR UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR
TO RECORD MESSAGES FROM
ALL THE OTHER TRANSLATORS.
YOU WERE SPYING
ON THE DELEGATES.
YOU ACCIDENTALLY TRIGGERED
AN I.D. PROTOCOL IN THE NETWORK.
I TRACKED IT BACK
TO THE SOURCE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU SURE KNOW WHAT EVERYONE ELSE
WAS TALKING ABOUT.
MAYBE SHE WAS AFTER A STORY.
IT DOESN'T MEAN
SHE WORKED FOR TERRA PRIME.
WE DID A BACKGROUND CHECK.
IN THE LAST MONTH, YOU MADE
THREE TRIPS TO THE LUNAR COLONY.
IS THAT A CRIME?
DEPENDS ON WHAT
YOU'RE DOING THERE.
-I WAS ON ASSIGNMENT.
-FOR?
MY NEWS AGENCY.
YOUR EDITOR CLAIMS
HE NEVER SENT YOU.
LOOK,
IF I'M UNDER ARREST --
TWO OF MY CREWMEN ARE
AT ORPHEUS MINING COMPLEX.
-WE'VE LOST CONTACT WITH THEM.
-I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT YOUR --
ARE THEY IN DANGER?
I WANT TO SPEAK WITH COUNSEL.
NOW.
TAKE HER TO THE BRIG.
GET HER WHOEVER SHE WANTS.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Bridge to Captain Archer.
I'M SORRY, TRAVIS.
ARCHER.
A large vessel is taking off
from the mining facility.
-CAN YOU IDENTIFY IT?
-Sir, sensors indicate
it is the mining facility.
-[ BEEPING ]
WE'RE BEING HAILED.
-IT'S STARFLEET COMMAND.
IGNORE THEM.
REACTOR STATUS?
-READY.
-YOU'RE GOING TO WARP?
-A 5-SECOND BURST.
-INSIDE THE SYSTEM?
WE'LL BE LUCKY
IF WE DON'T FLY APART.
I PLAN ON LUCK.
GO.
10 SECONDS.
[ metal clanking ]
HAIL THEM.
PURSUIT COURSE, TRAVIS.
AYE.
NO RESPONSE, SIR.
TELL STARFLEET COMMAND
WE'RE GOING AFTER THEM.
WE'RE IN MARS ORBIT.
ALL SYSTEMS FUNCTIONING.
THAT WAS A MAGNIFICENT PIECE
OF FLYING, DANIEL.
THAT'S YET TO COME.
IMPRESS ME AGAIN.
TAKING US DOWN.
LET'S SEE IT.
SLOWING OUR DESCENT.
TIE US IN.
IT'S OURS.
LET'S TAKE IN THE VIEW.
THIS IS WHERE IT ALL BEGINS.
JOSIAH.
-THEY'RE ON THE SURFACE.
-WHERE?
THEY'VE LANDED
NEAR THE VERTERON ARRAY.
IT'S USED TO REDIRECT COMETS.
-[ BEEPING ]
-THEY'RE SENDING A SUBSPACE
MESSAGE ON ALL FREQUENCIES.
MY NAME IS
JOHN FREDERICK PAXTON.
I'VE JUST TAKEN OVER
THE VERTERON ARRAY ON MARS.
I CAN NOW FIRE ON ANY SHIP
OR FACILITY IN THE SYSTEM.
[ BEEPING ]
HE'S TARGETED EARTH'S MOON.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF USING THIS WEAPON AGAIN,
PROVIDED THAT EVERY SINGLE
NON-HUMAN IN OUR SYSTEM
LEAVES IMMEDIATELY.
A NEW ERA IS AT HAND,
AN ERA WHICH WILL
EXPOSE THE CONCEPT
OF INTERSPECIES UNITY
AS AN ABSOLUTE
AND VICIOUS LIE.
AN ERA THAT WILL WITNESS
THE ADVENT
OF A HUMAN-CENTRIC
CONSCIOUSNESS
THAT WILL PLACE OUR WORLD
BEFORE ALL OTHERS.
AS OF THIS MOMENT,
MANKIND CASTS OFF THE SHACKLES
OF ALIEN INTERFERENCE,
AND NOW DETERMINES
ITS OWN FATE.
TERRA PRIME...FOREVER.