[ T'Pol ] Previously,
on " Enterprise"...
Today, we have assembled representatives
of numerous worlds
To forge an unprecedented alliance.
It's almost possible to forget
what she represents.
According to every analysis,
this child is the offspring
of Commander Tucker and Commander T'Pol.
We think Terra Prime is involved
and it has something to do with the child.
Find it, you'll have the answers.
-I've never been pregnant, Trip.
-Then how do you explain all this?
She's not here to do a story
on Enterprise, Travis.
She's a spy.
I'm returning Earth
to its rightful owners.
I have just taken over
the Verteron array on Mars.
I can now fire on any ship
or facility in the system.
I have no intention
of using this weapon again,
Provided that every single
non-Human in our system
Leaves immediately.
I know there will be questions.
We've been dealing with non-humans
-For almost a century...
-Block that transmission.
He's on every frequency.
The signal's going system-wide.
Target his ship.
Take out their communications.
He's tied his warp reactor into the array.
If we hit him, it'll take out half
of Utopia colony.
Open a channel to Starfleet.
Judge the evidence for yourselves.
-[Beeping]
-Everything's jammed.
The citizen-soldiers of Terra prime
Will act to protect you against
the most dangerous enemy
that humanity has ever faced.
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And I will see my dream
come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna
change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart
will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength
of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend
or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got, I've got ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
[ Paxton ] Do not be deceived.
This is no ordinary, innocent child.
This is an alien-Human hybrid,
living proof of what will happen
if we allow ourselves
To be submerged
in an interstellar coalition.
Our genetic heritage...
I want that transmission blocked.
We're trying. We can't break
through the signal.
Then find some way to contact Enterprise.
I want to speak to Archer.
Terra prime is dedicated
to the protection of life
in all of its diversity.
So for the next 24 hours,
we guarantee safe passage
To all aliens leaving our solar system.
So long as non-humans keep
to their own worlds...
Scan Paxton's ship for Vulcan bio-signs.
Get a transporter lock
on the baby and T'Pol.
But if any alien, if one single alien
remains after the deadline,
terra prime will defend
the sovereignty
Of every single Human being,
and we will begin by destroying
the institution
Whose blind arrogance and moral cowardice
Have put us all at risk,
Starfleet Command.
We do not seek war,
but if the aliens do not leave
and force us to fight,
I make this solemn promise to all
of the sons and daughters of Earth...
Our future will be secure
Because humanity will prevail.
He's targeted us with the array.
Apparently, they don't like being scanned.
Get us out of here.
-Damage?
-Massive power surge.
[ Malcolm ] We've lost half our relays.
The beam was only 2%
of the array's total output.
-He could have vaporized us.
-We'll consider ourselves warned.
Set a course to Earth.
If you'll excuse me.
Of course.
Ambassador.
Spontaneous demonstrations
have already begun
around the Vulcan compound.
Isolated incidents, I'm sure.
There are protesters chanting
outside the Andorian embassy.
[ Crowd chanting ]
And they're using words
that aren't in the universal translator.
It's obvious Paxton's ultimatum
is part of a coordinated plan.
Why are we all still here?
We could be obliterated
at any second.
Paxton's a fanatic,
but he's a man of his word.
He won't act before his deadline's up.
The deadline aside, the fact
that Paxton has the support
Of so many of your people
is almost as troubling.
I agree.
Earthmen talk about uniting worlds,
But your own planet is deeply divided.
Perhaps you're not quite ready
to host this conference.
Paxton's holding two of my officers
hostage at the array.
We can't attack it.
The council's aware of that.
If you can't bring yourself
to fire on them,
another captain can be assigned
to Enterprise.
-No one will think less of you.
-It's not just the hostages.
Any attack on the array
will trigger a massive explosion
That could kill thousands of colonists.
This wasn't an easy
decision for the council.
The potential for disaster's even greater
than you think.
[ Samuels ] Over the next 30 months,
the terraforming project
Has 14 comets set to collide with Mars.
Without the array to divert them
toward the polar caps,
The comets could hit anywhere,
even the domed cities.
I'll take in a small team.
We'll break into the facility
and stop them.
Paxton can destroy any ship
that approaches Mars.
If he can't see us... He can't destroy us.
It's unharmed, just as I said.
-[ Beeping ]
-her medical readings appear normal.
There's nothing normal about it.
She's not an "it."
How did you obtain our genetic material?
The child is a binary clone?
They'd need cells from both of us.
The medical freezers on your ship
hold bio-samples from your entire crew.
Terra prime has supporters everywhere.
Someone on Enterprise helped you? Who?
I've let you see your daughter.
That's my half of the bargain.
Now it's your turn.
I need to make modifications on my ship.
I'm listening.
I need you to refine my targeting system.
You really think I'm gonna help you
turn that array into a weapon?
You really think
I'm gonna give you a choice?
Two meetings in the span of a week.
People might start to talk.
I don't like it any more than you do.
So, you want to go to Mars
and you need my help.
-You know the situation.
-I believe I'm aware of the broad strokes.
I also understand Paxton's tapped
into the planetary sensor grid.
No one can get within 1,000 kilometers
of the verteron array
without being detected.
-And you're going to tell me how.
-What makes you think
I even have that information?
Because your section routinely
thinks about the unthinkable,
And because you'd never miss
a chance to put me in your debt.
You're a good judge of character.
The grid was designed to function
in the planet's original atmosphere,
But terra forming's made the air
much thicker.
How does that help us?
Sections of the grid
continually need recalibration
And are prone to false signals.
You can exploit that weakness.
The good news is, with terraforming,
There's no more need for pressure suits
in the lowland.
Oxygen, yes.
Thermal garments.
According to this, if we keep our altitude
Less than 10 meters above the surface,
Paxton won't see us.
You'll still need
to reach the surface undetected.
That part's taken care of,
without your help.
So, the student has surpassed the teacher.
When you're finished with Mars,
why don't you come work for me?
I've got quite enough to keep me busy
on Enterprise.
And if Archer's coalition is formed,
Enterprise could be busier than ever.
Indeed?
Well, then I imagine this will be the last
time we meet.
Always the optimist.
Good luck...
Malcolm.
Comet Burke, deflected by the array
eight years ago.
Set to hit the north pole of Mars at dawn.
-[ Samuels ] You're not serious.
-I have experience with comets, sir.
Compared to penetrating Xindi defenses,
This'll be a walk in the park.
But that's only 14 hours from now.
What happens if this plan
of yours doesn't work?
Enterprise will destroy the array
as ordered.
All the rocking in the world
Will not make that child Vulcan or human.
Human and Vulcan genes
produced this child,
Which indicates our two species
have more similarities than differences.
Don't you realize that baby is...
That baby's as much a threat
to your species as it is to mine?
She's not a threat.
That child is a crossbreed freak.
How many generations before our genome
is so diluted
That the word "human" is nothing
more than a footnote in some medical text?
The same thing could happen
to your people,
or don't you care about that?
Neither of our species
is what it was a million years ago
nor what it will become in the future.
Life is change.
Change in this case means extinction,
and I for one will not let that baby
Bring humanity to that point.
I won't let you hurt her.
I won't have to.
What does that mean?
We're within range.
Bridge to engineering.
-[ Communicator beeps ]
-Kelby here.
We're coming up on the comet.
I'm on it, sir.
This is it, people. Cycle the ports.
Ensign, rig the intakes
for cometary debris.
Yes, sir.
-[ Communicator beeps ]
-engineering's good to go, sir.
You've got full impulse
and warp standing by.
All right, Travis.
Let's hitch a ride to Mars.
Aye, aye, sir.
Thank you for seeing me.
What's so urgent?
I never got my lawyer.
You'll have to talk to the captain.
Apparently, he's busy.
We all are.
That's it?
I don't work for Terra prime.
I work for Starfleet intelligence.
That's not possible.
[ Scoffs ]
You are not the only one
who wants to serve his people.
If you were an S.I. Agent,
you'd be out of this brig
With one call to your division head.
And everyone on Enterprise
would know who I am,
including the real Terra prime operative.
[ Communicator beeps ]
Mayweather. Go ahead.
[ Malcolm ] We're ready for you
in the launch bay.
On my way.
You know I'm going to tell
the captain about this.
He won't believe you.
Probably not.
Why--why are you telling me this now?
You're going after Paxton.
If someone on Enterprise
is working for him,
he could know you're coming.
So you're revealing all of this
because you're worried about me.
Yes.
I'm touched.
Travis, wait!
You're not going to manipulate me again.
Goodbye.
Keep the sensors locked on the array.
The moment it powers up--
I won't hesitate, sir.
I remember when you used to jump
every time the engines hiccuped.
I still do.
I'm just better at hiding it.
Captain.
Don't get too used to that chair.
I'm gonna want it back.
Understood.
You know, I never used to like Vulcans
all that much myself.
They always seemed so smug,
making us jump through hoops
For every little advance
in warp technology,
and they knew the answers all along.
So what was it with you?
The ears?
The fact that they're vegetarian?
They're not human.
Well, can't deny that.
And they sat by while millions
of our people died.
World War III.
We didn't make contact with the Vulcans
until 10 years after the war.
But they were up there
with their superior technology.
They could have stopped it,
but they didn't.
I think it suited their plans.
A devastated Earth was much easier
for them to control.
Is that the kind of paranoid
crap Paxton's been feeding you?
Get back to work.
You ever actually met a Vulcan?
Your friend, she's the first.
If you got to know some,
Actually took the time to talk with one,
yeah, well, you obviously
did more than talk.
And look what you got for your trouble.
Some half-Human thing.
[ Scoffs ]
Go ahead.
Okay.
Ugh!
[ Grunting ]
You're a traitor.
[ Groaning ]
A traitor to humanity.
[ Rumbling ]
Hull plating's steady at 94%.
[ Beeping ]
What's wrong with the inertial dampeners?
We need to maintain
an erratic flight profile
So we look like a chunk of the comet.
[ Beeping ]
Thirty minutes to the atmosphere.
I'm taking us closer to the nucleus.
It's going to start getting
a little rough.
Start?
Would you like me to give you something?
Uh, I've already had the maximum dosage.
-Here's a bag.
-[ Grunts ]
There's nothing aliens like better
Than to see us fighting one another.
-Where's T'Pol and the baby?
-They're together.
You'll eat as soon
as you finish your work.
I am finished.
All you've done is try to sabotage
the targeting system.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Please. I've been monitoring your work
from the control center.
To be honest, I'd have been disappointed
if you hadn't tried to sabotage the array.
But you did. Which proves
you're a man of principle.
That's why I know you're going to refine
the array just as you promised.
I told you I'd make modifications
to your ship, not your weapon.
In two hours, I am going to fire
a Verteron beam
Directly at Starfleet command.
Now, with this targeting system
the way it is, I will hit Starfleet,
But I'll also take out half
of San Francisco along with it.
I need a scalpel, not a bludgeon.
I don't care what you need.
Starfleet's been warned,
if that's what concerns you.
Now, you can either help me,
And a few empty buildings
will be destroyed,
Or you refuse me, and millions may die.
You told Starfleet when you're planning
to fire the array.
And you don't think they're gonna blast
This facility off the face of the planet?
If you're so eager for a bloodbath,
a bloodbath is what you will get.
Put him in detention.
And make sure he has a news screen.
I want him to see the bodies when
they start to pull them from the rubble.
Hello.
I'm your mother.
You're going to need a name.
We should discuss that with your father.
The gravity's starting to tear
the comet apart.
We're picking up ionization
from the upper atmosphere.
-[ Whooshing ]
-What was that?
The engine shut down,
but there were no warning lights.
The console's locked up.
[ Beeping ]
Hull plating's offline.
Hull temperature's climbing.
We're coming in too hot.
[ Travis ] Bypassing auto flight control.
Switching to manual.
[ Malcolm ] At this speed?
[ Travis ] We're out of options.
-Ground proximity?
-[ Archer ] Five seconds to impact.
Well, that was fun.
Can we do it again?
[ Grunts ]
[ Beeping ]
A mark 3 interlock.
The closer we get, the more we risk
Being spotted by Paxton's sensors.
-Get close to that ridge line.
-I was thinking the same thing.
You'll want to keep your arms
inside the vehicle at all times.
-[ Malcolm ] Thirty two.
-[ Phlox ] Hmm?
[ Malcolm ] This is the 32nd planet
I've set foot on.
[ Phlox ] Two hundred forty eight.
[ Archer ] The Verteron array
is on the other side of that rise.
We'll head through there.
[ Paxton ] I'm told you
have something to say to me.
-In private.
-I keep no secrets from my men.
You and I both know
that's not true.
Josiah, give us the room.
I'll be outside.
My daughter's ill.
You'll arrange for medical care at once.
No one leaves this facility.
You will provide immediate
transport for my child,
Commander Tucker, and myself.
The hospital at Utopia colony
will be suitable
Until Enterprise arrives.
[ Chuckles ]
What, have you been inhaling
the atmosphere?
What makes you think you can dictate
terms to me?
This.
Taggart's syndrome.
Since you obviously didn't die by age 20,
You're receiving treatment.
-Rigellian gene therapy?
-You're not a doctor.
The very thing you're warning humans
to avoid is what's keeping you alive.
Alien knowledge, freely shared.
You're not only a terrorist,
you're a hypocrite.
This is not the time for timidity
and second-guessing.
We cannot afford to doubt ourselves.
Colonel Green also said,
"to be Human is to be pure."
Under his rule,
you would have been euthanized
for having a genetic disorder.
I'm not the first significant leader
Who failed to measure up
to his own ideals.
You're not significant.
History will determine that!
So go ahead.
Tell my followers what you wish.
See if they take the word
of an alien over mine.
What's wrong with your child?
Elevated white blood cell count,
low-grade fever.
Well, its two halves are warring
with one another.
Alien and human. Conflict was inevitable.
Josiah.
Your child and the coalition of planets
both doomed from the beginning.
[ Beeping ]
[ Malcolm ] Ten meters.
Paxton's deadline is up.
We have to face an unpleasant reality.
Captain Archer's mission has failed.
Paxton will need two minutes to power up
the array before he can fire.
-Two minutes?
-It's enough.
I'm not prepared to take that chance.
Your estimates could be wrong.
I won't destroy the array unless
we have no other choice.
I understand your reluctance.
I'm following orders.
I'm giving you new orders.
Do it now.
-Sorry, sir.
-I can have you relieved of duty.
Actually, I can only be relieved
by a higher-ranking officer
in my chain of command.
Open a channel to admiral Gardner.
Belay that order.
I won't risk exposing our position
By breaking radio silence.
You're risking the lives of hundreds
of thousands of people.
I know what I'm doing.
[ Beeping ]
The guard's still walking away.
There's another guard approaching.
-Took you long enough.
-Where's T'Pol?
Crew quarters. But Paxton's getting ready
to fire the array.
If he powers it up...
Enterprise has orders
to destroy the complex.
I've spoken to our operatives.
There's no indication that the Vulcans
have withdrawn
from their consulates
in Canberra or Berlin.
I never expected them to comply.
Let's get this done.
I'm picking up a power surge in the array.
You're out of time.
Destroy the complex now.
Take us in, full impulse.
Charge weapons.
Josiah, begin the firing sequence.
[ Beeping ]
Target locked.
Give the order.
Coordinates locked in.
Two minutes to pulse activation.
[ Groans ]
Ah!
Step away from the controls.
Jonathan Archer.
The man who delivered us from the Xindi.
Well, look at you now.
Archer to Enterprise.
Go ahead, Captain.
We're inside the control room.
Standing by.
Shut it down.
Main controls are in there.
[ Groans ]
[ Alarm blaring ]
90 seconds
to pulse activation.
[ Grunts ]
[ Archer ] The room's depressurizing.
Get Malcolm out of here.
Go!
Plasma grid...
Control panel.
I know the reason
you've turned your back on humanity.
I blame your father.
He wanted the secrets
of warp technology so badly,
he allowed the Vulcans to turn him
into their pet human.
And you, well, the sins of the father...
[ Beeping ]
Plasma grid off line.
Firing sequence aborted.
My father never asked anything
from anyone.
His mining operations
transformed the moon...
From a mere colony
into a completely self-sufficient world,
And that is how we should
go to the stars.
Taking the worlds
we need and taming them,
With Human hands and Human minds
and Human souls.
That might have worked
for the moon,
But the galaxy's a lot more crowded
than we thought.
That's not our problem.
It's an opportunity.
It's over, Paxton.
We're each his father's child.
I've been a miner all my life.
You get used to the low oxygen.
[ Beeping ]
-Firing sequence resumed.
-[ Coughing ]
Pulse activation in 30 seconds.
[ Both grunting ]
[ Beeping ]
Pulse activation in 15 seconds.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six--
I've locked the sequence.
You can't stop it from firing.
-Five, four...
-I've locked it!
Three, two, one.
Pulse activated.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Terra prime forever.
[ Tucker ] Looks like Paxton's
aim was off.
[ Gasping] with a little help from you.
Maybe a little.
Commander.
She's dying.
Captain's star log, January 22, 2155.
Enterprise is returning to Earth.
Paxton is in custody, but
the consequences of his actions
Continue to affect us all.
I guess we shouldn't
keep calling her "she."
Elizabeth.
My sister would have liked that.
It appears my initial prognosis
was incorrect.
It's genetic.
Her Vulcan and Human
DNA aren't compatible.
Is there anything you can do?
I'm attempting to stabilize
her nucleotides,
But there's never been a child like her.
Her name is Elizabeth.
I can't figure out
why the console locked up
At the same time the engines shut down.
It does seem a bit coincidental.
[ Sighs ]
Flight control and engine power
are routed separately
Until they reach...
That junction.
The panel's open.
If ionized gas got in here,
It could have melted the primary
circuits of both systems.
It could have been knocked loose
by an impact.
-[Beeping]
-No. It's been forced.
This was deliberate.
[ Door chimes ]
Come in.
On your feet, sir.
Shuttlepod 1 was sabotaged.
-Sabotaged?
-We nearly crashed!
-Is this your signature?
-Yeah.
-You think I had something to do with it?
-Is there any reason why we shouldn't?
That's a shuttlepod maintenance log.
Commander Tucker took me off that team
When he came back from Columbia.
Who replaced you?
-Who?
-Ensign Masaro.
They really want to postpone
the conference?
"Postpone" is a diplomatic way
of saying it's dead.
Paxton's unnerved them,
and there's not a lot
I've been able to say
to change their minds.
-[ Communicator beeps ]
-Excuse me, sir.
Sato. Go ahead.
It's Archer.
Are you still with Samuels?
We're in the mess hall.
Is ensign Masaro there?
No, I don't see him, sir.
We think Masaro may be working
for Terra Prime.
Samuels may be in danger.
Reed and Mayweather are on their way.
Wait here, sir.
Samuels is in here.
He's safe.
Captain.
[ Gasps ]
-You don't want to do this.
-I have to.
Give me the phase pistol.
That's an order.
I can't, sir.
Ensign.
I wanted you to know...
I'm sorry.
I believed in what we were doing.
Tell my parents I'm sorry.
[ Sobbing ]
I never wanted anyone to get hurt.
Ensign.
[ Laser fire ]
[ Thuds ]
I wish I could do more.
I know.
When you invited me to join this crew,
I thought it would be an interesting
diversion for a few months.
Some time away from
the complications of family,
which on Denebola
can be extremely complicated.
I didn't expect to gain another family.
It hurts as if she were my own child.
Make something good
come from this, Captain.
Fellow delegates, this last week,
we've seen what humans
can be at their worst.
But we cannot, we must not
use that as an excuse to end
the dream that began here.
For then the demons
of our past will have won.
Instead, I want to look to the future
And begin by honoring
the people responsible
for our being here tonight.
They represent all of us at our best.
Up until about 100 years ago,
There was one question
that burned in every human
That made us study the stars
and dream of traveling to them.
Are we alone?
Our generation is privileged...
To know the answer to that question.
We are all explorers,
driven to know,
what's over the horizon,
What's beyond our own shores?
Yet...
The more I've experienced...
The more I've learned...
That no matter how far we travel...
Or how fast we get there...
The most profound discoveries
Are not necessarily beyond that next star.
They're within us...
Woven into the threads that bind us...
All of us... to each other.
The final frontier begins in this hall.
Let's explore it together.
I hear the conference is back on track.
It's a first step. The captain
says it's going to take years
To work out the details.
But it'll happen,
and you're part of the reason why.
Just doing my job.
So was I.
I know.
If Vulcans and Andorians can get along,
you'd think we could.
A lot of details to work out.
Isn't that the fast way home?
The least I can do is give you a ride.
The launch bay's this way.
[ Door chimes ]
Come in.
The, uh...
Delegates at the conference,
they've, uh, asked
about the service for, um...
For Elizabeth.
They want to attend.
She was important.
[ Sighs ] There's something else.
[ Sniffles ] I spoke with Phlox.
It turns out there was a--
a flaw in the technique
That Paxton's doctors
used in the cloning process.
[ Clears throat ]
Human DNA and Vulcan DNA...
Phlox says there's no medical
reason why they can't combine.
So...
If a Vulcan and a human...
Ever decided to have a child...
It'd probably be okay.
[ Sniffles ]
And that's sort of comforting.