When are they expecting you in Brazil?
I told them a couple weeks
after the ceremony.
With all the receptions,
and then I'll need at least a week
to clear up the linguistic database.
After 10 years on this ship,
I bet it'll take a while getting
used to the humidity again.
And the bugs.
Does the captain have to give a speech?
He's working on it now.
He hates giving speeches.
He'll undoubtedly make every
effort to take no credit.
Undoubtedly.
That'd be like zefram cochrane
not taking credit for warp drive.
How do you pronounce the name
of the second tellarite liberator?
-Challash?
-Shallash.
Shallash. Thanks.
How's it going, sir?
Whatever I write,
it sounds like I'm trying
to take credit for this.
Captain, Admiral Douglas is asking you
to approve the decommission protocols.
One thing at a time.
After the charter's signed,
I'll give him whatever he needs
to put Enterprise in mothballs.
[crewman] All senior staff,
report to the Bridge.
[Riker] Computer, freeze program.
Save from this time index.
[computer] Program saved.
End program.
♪ It's been a long road ♪
♪ Getting from there to here ♪
♪ It's been a long time ♪
♪ But my time is finally near ♪
♪ And I will see my dream
Come alive at last ♪
♪ I will touch the sky ♪
♪ And they're not gonna
Hold me down no more ♪
♪ No, they're not gonna change my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got faith ♪
♪ Of the heart ♪
♪ I'm going where my heart will take me ♪
♪ I've got faith to believe ♪
♪ I can do anything ♪
♪ I've got strength of the soul ♪
♪ And no one's gonna bend or break me ♪
♪ I can reach any star ♪
♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ I've got, I've got ♪
-♪ I've got ♪
-♪ I've got faith ♪
♪ Faith of the heart ♪
[Riker] First officer's personal log,
Stardate 47457.1.
With the unexpected arrival of
Admiral Pressman, my old C.O.,
I find myself in an awkward position.
Counselor Troi has suggested
I might get a few insights
by calling up an historic holoprogram.
[Troi] Are you sure you don't want to
talk about what happened?
I've told you everything I can.
If it's a question
of breaking a promise...
Not a promise. An order.
Have you learned anything
on the holodeck about breaking orders?
Not yet.
I've gone back a couple of days
earlier to get a perspective.
But I really don't see
how this is gonna help.
That's why you run a starship,
and I'm a counselor.
Reed's shorter than I thought he'd be.
Maybe the program's off.
No, I'm sure it's fine.
It's just, you expect
larger-than-life people
to be larger-than-life.
-Has the Andorian hailed them?
-Not yet.
You might want to leap ahead
to that point.
It's where things start really happening.
And you should consider
taking over the galley.
Why?
Well, Starfleet ships didn't
have counselors in those days,
But the chef on the first
Enterprise came pretty close.
I read almost everybody confided in him.
I'll keep that in mind.
-Supper?
-You bet.
-I'll give you an update.
-OK.
That's impossible.
Shran's been dead for what, three years?
[beeping]
This is quite a surprise.
I'm sorry, pink-skin, but it was essential
certain people believed
I had met my demise.
Including me.
I know it's been a while, but as I recall,
you still owe me a favor.
I remember.
But this isn't a good time, Shran.
I assume you know where we're heading.
I may no longer be a member
of the imperial guard,
but I'm aware of the proposed coalition.
It's more than a proposal.
We're on our way to earth
to sign the charter.
The ceremony isn't for three days.
If my plan works,
you'll be home in plenty of time.
[scoffs]
I'm afraid a detour is out
of the question right now.
My child's been abducted!
Kidnapped. You owe me.
You never told me you had a child.
Jhamel gave birth five years ago.
A daughter. They've taken her.
Who?
Former associates. It's a long story.
You need to let me come aboard.
Set a rendezvous course.
Computer, freeze program.
[beeps]
Advance ahead one hour.
Switch to objective mode.
[Shran] Who would have thought
civilian life would be more dangerous
than commanding a ship
for the imperial guard.
I still don't understand why you left.
You were a hero.
A hero with a family.
I always believed
that change was a good thing.
I was a fool.
-Why would you fake your own death?
-I made some poor choices.
Picked the wrong friends,
people involved in questionable
business ventures.
They think I took something
that belonged to them.
With the help of some old
colleagues from the guard,
I managed to make myself disappear.
It worked... for nearly three years.
-Your friends found you?
-Six months ago.
I've been on the move ever since.
They took her in the middle of the night.
I was in the next room, asleep!
Useless!
It's been a week.
They say if I don't return
what's theirs, they'll kill her.
Then give them what they want.
I don't have it! I never did.
But you have a plan.
[Shran] It cost me everything I had,
but I managed to find out
where they've taken her.
They're on a trading outpost, Rigel X.
-I'm familiar with it.
-I know these men quite well, Captain.
I can outwit them. I've done it before.
But I'll need at least seven men.
You have to help me. It's my little girl.
He's an admitted criminal.
You said so yourself.
He said he fell in
with some disreputable people.
That doesn't make him a criminal.
If we're late for the ceremony,
it'll have far-reaching consequences.
If Shran hadn't helped us,
I never would have gotten aboard
the Xindi weapon.
Have you forgotten that?
This alliance is based
on friendship and loyalty,
exactly what Shran is
looking for right now.
I don't trust him.
You don't trust Andorians. You never have.
Thank god the Vulcan council
is a little more enlightened than you are.
If they're willing to forge
an alliance with Andoria,
the least you can do is give
Shran the benefit of the doubt.
When we met 10 years ago,
I didn't trust you.
For that matter,
I didn't trust any Vulcans.
You helped me get past that, remember?
I listened to you.
Now it's your turn to listen to me.
I can't turn my back on him, T'pol.
-Try to understand.
-I'll try.
[Archer] By the way...
Drop by the galley when you get a moment.
Chef's trying to come up with a menu
for our last dinner together.
He wants to know
everybody's favorite dish.
[T'pol] There are 83 crew members aboard.
Just go see him, all right?
[whining]
[Archer] Don't worry.
Chef's promised
at least six kinds of cheese.
[T'pol] I appreciate the gesture,
but it's not necessary to
prepare a special dish for me.
Come on.
I've already started to reduce
the plomeek broth.
All I need to know is
which roots you prefer.
In that case, I prefer to be surprised.
Pull up a chair. I could use the company.
I heard a rumor I may be whipping up
some Andorian cabbage soup tonight.
We have already lost five hours
picking up Shran's shuttle.
Now we're going to lose
at least another day
diverting our course to Rigel.
His child's in danger.
Is there anything aboard
this ship you don't know?
Jonathan is a compassionate man.
You should know that by now.
His compassion has gotten us
into trouble on many occasions.
We could miss this ceremony.
Don't worry. I've got a hunch
you're gonna make it.
-Tea?
-Thank you.
Phlox has given me his largest
Edosian suckerfish.
Excuse me?
Looks like a catfish.
I'm hoping it tastes like one.
Commander Tucker's crazy for catfish.
Do you ever miss him?
I spent the morning with him,
recalibrating the plasma array.
That's not what I mean.
If you're referring
to our intimate relationship,
that's been over for six years.
But the question remains, do you miss him?
I'm Vulcan. I don't miss people.
Sorry. I forgot.
Is he as concerned as you
about making this ceremony?
Trip rarely questions
the Captain's decisions.
He doesn't strike me as someone
who follows orders blindly.
He's not.
He simply tends to agree with
the Captain most of the time.
He trusts him.
Would you peel these for me?
Before I joined this crew,
I never could have imagined anything
more important than following orders.
And now?
Humans believe that sometimes
you have to follow your instincts.
Very illogical approach,
but one I've come to embrace.
-Computer, freeze program.
-[computer beeps]
Thanks.
[beeping]
[door opens]
There you are.
Someone you know?
Someone I knew.
Pegasus?
Phil Wallace. Hell of a handball player.
Pressman was getting ready to promote him.
How many died?
Seventy one. All but nine of us.
How do you feel about learning
the ship wasn't destroyed?
What difference does it make?
71 people died.
You're feeling guilty.
You think, in some way,
you were responsible?
You're the empath. Why don't you tell me?
I think it's something else,
something about seeing that ship again.
-Why don't we change the subject? OK?
-OK.
How did things go on the holodeck?
They picked up the Andorian.
They're on their way to Rigel X.
I was referring to any insight
you may have gained.
I took your advice about the chef.
You were right. T'pol opened up to me.
-Have you met with Commander Tucker?
-No, I haven't made it to Engineering yet.
-Have you spent any time on the NX-01?
-I've never run the program.
What about the ship itself?
I think I went when I was a little girl,
but I get all those museum ships mixed up.
Now's your chance. Come on down with me.
I have an appointment in an hour.
I'll get you back in plenty of time.
Come on.
Our Brig is bigger than this.
A lot of things change in 200 years.
Watch yourself!
No fish tank.
How could archer survive
without a fish tank?
Allow me.
He does have a dog, though.
Right, I remember. One of the musketeers.
Porthos.
Oh, comfy.
No seat for the first officer?
Perhaps, Archer wasn't as fussy
as Captain Picard,
when it came to people
sitting in his chair.
[beeping]
I remember seeing one of these
in a photograph.
Kirk's ship had them, I think.
Engineering's down this way.
There's something lonely about
a ship without its crew.
Computer, add an appropriate
crew complement, objective mode.
[beeping]
That's better.
If you recall, Rigel X is filled
with a very unsavory element.
And I rather doubt Shran's scheme
will be quite as simple as he claims.
I can't imagine the Captain would put us
in jeopardy this close
to signing the charter.
-I don't like it.
-[electronic humming]
What exactly are you doing?
These injectors need to be
purged every six months.
Are the deuterium filters clear?
-We've done all but three.
-All right.
-Make it quick.
-Aye, sir.
Well, what's the point?
This ship will be joining
the mothball fleet next week.
I pretty much built this engine.
Plan to take care of it as long as I can.
[sighs]
Been a hell of a run, Malcolm.
I never thought it would come to an end.
All good things...
Captain thinks there'll be
another Enterprise before too long.
I imagine.
It won't be the same.
That's OK.
Come on.
It's sad.
Commander Tucker had no idea
he wouldn't make it back.
How reliable are your sources?
[Shran] They're criminals,
but honorable ones.
They promise me that Talla's
being held here. At upper level 4.
Have you fashioned the amethyst?
The photograph you gave us
had poor resolution,
but I'm confident our
replication will look authentic.
The Teneebian amethyst
they think I stole was flawless.
They'll undoubtedly have
magnifying equipment with them.
They'll need a spectral micrometer
to see it's a fabrication.
How many do you expect to show up?
-Computer, freeze program.
-[beeping]
-He's cute.
-Don't get any ideas.
Reg will be furious if I'm late.
-Are you gonna stay?
-[Riker] Yeah, for a little while.
Good luck. Computer, arch.
Computer, how long
before they reach Rigel X?
[computer] Sixteen hours, 22 minutes.
Advance to that point.
Stay in objective mode.
Move into a stationary orbit.
[Travis] Aye, sir.
Put a team together.
Meet us in the launch bay.
[Tucker] Captain,
can I have a word with you?
We can handle this without you.
-Well, that's flattering.
-You know what I mean.
You've got the biggest day
of your life coming up.
A lot of people are counting
on you being there.
I appreciate you worrying
about me, but I'll be fine.
You don't need to be putting
yourself in harm's way.
I'm telling you, we can take care of it.
Rigel was the first place
we visited, remember?
Now it's gonna be the last.
Poetic justice.
Why should you have all the fun?
We're going through the troposphere.
Might get a little bumpy.
Have you been down to see chef yet?
First thing this morning. You?
He talked about you.
-Me?
-Us.
[Tucker] What about us?
It's not important.
[chuckles] Why'd you bring it up, then?
[rumbling]
Do you ever miss me?
-You mean...
-Yes.
You know how long it's been?
That's not what I asked you.
Well, um...
Yeah, I guess, sometimes.
I haven't thought about
those days in a long time.
Benefit of being a Vulcan.
After speaking with chef,
I realized we may never
see each other again.
-What are you talking about?
-We're taking different assignments.
-There's no way of knowing--
-There's every way of knowing.
I can guarantee you
we're not gonna lose touch.
Stop thinking like that.
However long it may be,
I believe I'm going to miss you.
[Archer] Archer to Shuttlepod 2.
Go ahead, sir.
[Archer] Shran's made contact.
Everything's set.
-I'll lead you in.
-Understood.
[Alien] Stop there.
Unless I'm mistaken,
I thought you had no idea
where the amethyst was.
Where's my daughter?
Funny how a missing child is
a way to jog the memory,
eh, Shran?
Where is she?
I thought you were happily married.
Who's the Vulcan?
I'm not interested in your associates,
so don't question mine.
Put the case down and open it.
We want the child first.
I could shoot you both.
You'll never get this case open,
I promise you.
You let a female
negotiate for you, eh, Shran?
You heard her.
-Are you all right?
-I'm hungry.
Now open the case.
[beeping]
Set it down.
Now back up.
Let her take the girl.
Fine, but you stay.
One step, and this little blue beauty
won't have a father to come home to.
I want you to go with T'pol.
You'll be safe with her.
She'll find you something to eat.
Obey your father.
Now step back.
[beeping]
-What are you doing?
-[beeping]
[screams]
Stand still, and you won't be harmed!
[shouts indistinctly]
Ugh!
Aah!
Hold on!
[grunting]
Thanks, boss.
Anytime.
You're certain that it won't be a problem?
[Archer] I'll feel more comfortable
getting you away
from your friends at warp 4.
[Shran] My shuttle may be slow,
but their ships can barely make warp 2.
All the same,
you'll be under your own power
by tomorrow night.
We'll contact your wife
and tell her to expect you
the next morning.
I told you my plan would
only take a few hours.
You're welcome.
[chuckles]
You should let phlox take a look at her
before you go to your quarters.
Whatever you say, captain.
Thanks, pink-skin.
[chuckles]
You must be getting tired
of saving my life.
I'm glad I didn't take your
advice about not coming along.
Yeah, you and me both.
Then again, you almost got
yourself killed down there.
Wouldn't have gone over
too big at the ceremony.
Signing documents are easy.
Training a new engineer...
that can be a real pain in the ass.
-[communicator beeps]
-[Data] Data to counselor Troi.
Yes, Data?
[Data] I was wondering if this might be
an appropriate time
to continue our discussion
on the long-term effects of space travel
on my positronic net.
Can I give you a rain check?
[Data] You may, check me for rain
if you wish, counselor,
but I assure you, I have no water in my--
-[door chimes]
-Data, I'll get back to you.
Come in.
I know it's past office hours.
What is it?
It won't be long before
they find the Pegasus.
You haven't made your decision.
[Troi] The holodeck?
They rescued the Andorian's daughter.
So, you're coming to the moment
of truth in there, as well.
I need you to promise
you'll keep this confidential.
You know I will.
What do you know
about the treaty of Algeron?
2311. It redefined
the Romulan neutral zone.
It also outlawed the use
of cloaking technology
on Starfleet vessels.
The Pegasus?
A secret group in Starfleet
security developed a prototype.
Pressman was put in charge of testing it.
That's why they're so eager to
find it before the Romulans do.
The accident, the 71 people who died...
-We were testing the cloaking device.
-It was covered up.
The nine of us who made it back
alive were sworn to secrecy.
And you've lived with that for 12 years?
And they want to pick the experiment up
where they left off.
Are you sure?
Pressman told me himself.
What they're doing is wrong.
It could jeopardize the treaty.
And you want to tell that
to Captain Picard.
I took an oath of secrecy.
Pressman still outranks the Captain.
Will...
You didn't get this far in your
career making easy decisions.
I'm confident you'll
make the right one now.
I wish I was.
[Reed] He was anything but tactful.
What his countrymen
might refer to as a hick.
For the life of me,
I couldn't understand
what captain archer saw in him.
Thinner. Roll it a little bit thinner,
like this.
Oh, yeah, right.
[Riker] Go on.
[Reed sighs] That's about it, really.
I used to think that first
impressions meant something.
I guess it's not always true.
You know, to be honest,
I didn't think he was
gonna last a month.
Old friend of the captain's or not.
And now, I can't imagine
what these last 10 years
would have been like without him.
Did you ever find yourself
attracted to him?
-Maybe a little.
-Hmm.
-I never really thought he was my type.
Didn't even graduate college,
he learned about engineering
working on boat engines, I think.
Never cared much about languages.
[snickers] Could barely speak English.
But he did have his moments.
I still find him kind of cute.
-Keep that to yourself.
-Always do.
Captain said they've known
each other a long time.
Close to 20 years.
He taught the captain how to scuba dive
somewhere off the coast of Florida.
You're pressing too hard.
Just slow, steady movement.
-Oh, sorry.
-No need to apologize.
They've got a shorthand
they use sometimes.
Comes from spending so much time together.
Did Trip ever take a swing at Picard?
-At who?
-Archer, Captain Archer?
Not that I know of.
When push comes to shove,
Commander Tucker usually ends up
doing the right thing.
[Travis] How am I doing?
Well, don't let it get too big.
Now fold it over.
There you go.
[laughing]
And he's always pushing himself,
Often to the point of exhaustion.
He's forced me to order him to
relax on more than one occasion.
To relax?
Yeah. Wasn't very keen on getting
neuropressure treatments from T'pol.
But it was that or become
addicted to sedatives.
If I remember correctly, that's when...
Their romance began? Mm. Precisely.
One time, he became so exhausted,
I had to demand he get six hours sleep.
He negotiated it down to four.
A very stubborn young man.
Ah! [chuckles] I quite enjoy this.
So did he follow your orders?
Didn't have a choice.
You've always got a choice.
So, you think this alliance is gonna hold?
We better hope so.
There are thousands
of planets within reach.
Got to start somewhere.
Who would have guessed?
Vulcans and Andorians in the same bed.
The Tellarites were never big
fans of the Andorians, either.
This is a special bottle of whiskey.
Zefram Cochrane gave it to my father
the day they broke ground
at the warp 5 complex.
And here we are... toasting to warp 7.
Here's to the next generation.
Written your speech yet?
I always cram before exams.
I've got three days left.
The biggest day of your life,
and you're gonna wait
until the night before.
It's the biggest day of our lives.
Oh, I hate to contradict you, Captain.
You're the man they're waiting to see.
[rumbling]
-[beeps]
-Archer to the Bridge. What's going on?
[T'pol] We're under attack, sir.
A small vessel.
[Archer] Who are they?
[T'pol] We don't know yet.
-[rumbling]
-[alarm ringing]
[T'pol] Intruder alert.
We've come for Shran and the child.
I thought you said their ship
couldn't catch up to us.
Remind me to mention that to Shran.
You're leaving me very little choice.
Shran left six hours ago. You're too late.
You're lying.
His shuttle is still in your launch bay.
-Kill him.
-[Tucker] Hold on! W-wait a minute!
-Trip, I'll take care of this.
-The hell you will.
I'll bring you to Shran.
I know where he is.
-I gave you an order, Commander.
-You heard me.
-I said I'd bring you to Shran.
-Trip!
Very well. Turn around, both of you!
-[Tucker] Hey, this guy's the Captain.
-That's enough.
[Tucker] He's my boss.
If I'm gonna disobey his order,
I don't want him coming along.
Trip, that's enough!
Listen, I won't do this if you kill him,
but could you please shut him up!
Stop.
You can't expect me
to just leave him here alive.
He's out cold. He's not
gonna cause any trouble.
Stay here.
If we're not back in 10 minutes, kill him.
Didn't you hear what I just said?
I won't help you if you kill him.
This might take longer than 10 minutes!
Take me to Shran,
or I'll kill him right now!
OK, OK!
I've got a better idea.
I'll bring Shran to us.
We don't have to go anywhere.
[grunts]
Be very careful.
You can all come see for yourselves.
This is just a comm station.
I'm gonna need to open this
so I can bypass the security protocols.
Is that OK?
As long as you keep your hands
where we can see them.
No problem.
[beeps]
All I need to do is connect this
to the relay inside that panel.
Stop. Open it for him.
If there's a weapon in there,
you're going to die before your Captain.
Satisfied?
Proceed.
Hurry up. You're running out of time.
There's just one other thing
I need to tell you.
You can all go straight to hell.
[screaming]
[groaning]
Trip?
[medic] He's not responding.
[Phlox] Add two percent syntho-surfactant!
[Archer] Doctor.
[Phlox] The plasma was super-heated.
It thermalized his lungs.
Initialize a hyperbaric chamber.
S-sorry about the r-rifle butt.
[breathing heavily]
-I was just trying to...
-I know, Trip.
Just take it easy. Everything's all right.
We gonna be late?
[Archer] No.
We're gonna be right on schedule.
I'll even have time to write my speech.
Great news.
Wait till they...
[gasps]
[beeping]
We need to get him into the chamber now!
Clear!
Need any help?
No, thank you.
For his parents?
Will they still be coming to the ceremony?
I told them I thought Trip
wouldn't want it any other way.
Don't forget this.
-I'd like to meet them.
-His parents?
Yes, I'd like to meet them.
They're a little eccentric.
I think you'll see where Trip
got his sense of humor.
My mother was somewhat eccentric, as well.
[Archer] I remember.
Trip told me, as the years went by,
that I would miss her less.
But he was wrong,
because I find myself missing her more.
[sighs] Why would he tell me that?
[sighs]
Time heals all wounds.
But absence makes the heart grow fonder.
I guess it's a little tricky.
Emotions have a way
of contradicting themselves.
And you wonder why we suppress them?
When I took command 10 years ago,
I saw myself as an explorer.
I thought all the risks would be worth it.
Because just beyond the next planet,
just beyond the next star,
there would be something magnificent,
something noble.
And now Trip is dead,
and I have to give a speech
about how worthwhile it's all been.
Trip would be the first to say
it was worthwhile.
Fried catfish with hush puppies.
Obviously, the captain mentioned
why I wanted to see you.
[chuckles]
Keep in mind, within a week,
I'll be eating the real thing.
Taking my folks down to mobile.
Nothing like a challenge.
Captain asked for meatloaf, didn't he?
I haven't spoken to him yet.
How about T'pol?
She won't be very cooperative.
You wait and see.
I've already started her plomeek broth.
All she has to do is choose
a few final ingredients.
She'll be down here in about an hour.
I hear we're on our way to pick up Shran.
Can you believe it?
We all thought he was dead and gone.
Well, don't you think the Captain's
cutting it a little close?
You mean, getting back to San Francisco?
Nah, he won't let anything
get in the way of that.
Trust me.
Can you spare one of those carrots?
-They're not peeled yet.
-That's OK.
You know, he'd never admit it,
but this thing means
a hell of a lot to him.
He's real proud to be one of
the people signing this charter.
And he ought to be.
You sound like a lifetime member
of the Jonathan Archer fan club.
I can count on one hand
the number of people I trust.
I don't mean trust like,
"I trust you aren't lying to me,"
or "i trust you won't steal my money."
I'm talking about
the kind of trust where...
You know someone's not gonna
hurt you, no matter what,
where you know they'll always
be there for you,
no matter how bad things get.
You ever know anybody like that?
Yeah.
One or two.
Well, I've got some packing
to do before I go back on duty.
You figured out what you're gonna do?
Do?
You gonna sign onto another ship,
or are you gonna open up
that little restaurant
in the Berkshires you told me about?
You know, I haven't decided yet.
You got any advice?
[chuckles] Nope.
[laughs]
But I'm sure you'll make the right choice.
Are you certain these are the right seats?
[Travis] Yep.
They don't seem very V.I.P. to me.
I'm sure the admiral
wanted us to have a view
that took in the scope of the occasion.
From this distance,
you can't tell an Andorian
from a Tellarite.
Oh, have you given an answer
to Captain still well yet?
I've asked him for a little more time,
until captain archer decides
what he's going to be doing.
I'll bet you a month's pay
he'll be on the bridge of a new ship.
He won't be able to resist one
of those warp 7 beauties.
I've heard he's already
been tapped for Admiral.
Malcolm's right.
They'll never keep him behind a desk.
It's very wise of you to stick with him.
That's exactly what I plan to do.
[beeping]
Please, stand still.
If you hadn't waited
until the last minute,
you would have had time
to memorize your speech.
You sound like my 9th-grade teacher.
There are dignitaries here
from 18 different worlds.
[chuckles] It's a good sign.
I wouldn't be surprised if this alliance
begins to expand before we know it.
You should be very proud
of yourself, Captain.
I'll be proud of myself
if I get this speech out in one piece.
That's not what I meant.
I know what you meant, Phlox,
and I appreciate it.
But this is not about me.
Why do so many humans
refuse to take credit
where credit is due?
There are times when modesty
and humility are quite illogical.
Whenever you're ready, sir.
Well, I've got three wives waiting.
I'd better go and join them.
I'd wish you good luck, Captain,
but you've always had an ample supply.
Thank you, doctor.
[Archer] You'd better get out there.
You don't want to miss me
screwing this thing up.
I'm going to remain down here,
if you don't mind.
You never did like crowds, did you?
You look...
very heroic.
[applause]
Is he nervous?
Wouldn't you be?
Oh, he'll be fine.
I had to memorize this speech
in grammar school.
You wish you could tell them all
that this alliance will
give birth to the Federation.
I think I'm ready to talk
to Captain Picard.
I should have done it a long time ago.
So, I guess we're through here.
-[applause]
-I guess we are.
Computer...
[beeps]
...End program.
[Picard] Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission...
[Kirk] To explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
[Archer] To boldly go
where no man has gone before.