- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
WHEN I WAS A BOY,
MY FATHER,
AVATAR AANG,
TOLD ME THE STORY
OF HOW HE AND HIS FRIENDS
HEROICALLY ENDED
THE HUNDRED-YEAR WAR.
AVATAR AANG
AND FIRE LORD ZUKO
TRANSFORMED
THE FIRE NATION COLONIES
INTO THE UNITED REPUBLIC
OF NATIONS,
A SOCIETY
WHERE BENDERS AND NON-BENDERS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD
COULD LIVE AND THRIVE TOGETHER
IN PEACE AND HARMONY.
THEY NAMED THE CAPITAL OF
THIS GREAT LAND REPUBLIC CITY.
AVATAR AANG ACCOMPLISHED
MANY REMARKABLE THINGS
IN HIS LIFE,
BUT SADLY HIS TIME IN THIS WORLD
CAME TO AN END.
AND, LIKE THE CYCLE
OF THE SEASONS,
THE CYCLE OF THE AVATAR
BEGAN ANEW.
- THE WHITE LOTUS HAS HONORED
MY FAMILY BY COMING.
THANK YOU.
- WELCOME.
- WE HAVE INVESTIGATED
MANY CLAIMS,
BOTH HERE
AND IN THE NORTHERN TRIBE.
ALL HAVE TURNED OUT
TO BE FALSE.
- THEN YOU SHOULD BE HAPPY
TO KNOW
YOUR SEARCH HAS COME
TO AN END.
- WHAT MAKES YOU SO SURE
YOUR DAUGHTER IS THE ONE?
- KORRA.
PLEASE COME IN HERE.
- I'M THE AVATAR.
YOU GOT TO DEAL WITH IT.
- [grunts]
- [yells]
- [groans]
- [grunts]
- SHE'S STRONG.
- SHE LACKS RESTRAINT.
- [whimpers]
[groans]
- WHOO-HOO!
HEY, WHY ALL THE DOOM
AND GLOOM, PEOPLE?
WE SHOULD BE CELEBRATING.
THREE ELEMENTS DOWN,
ONE TO GO.
- YOU'RE GETTING AHEAD
OF YOURSELF AS USUAL, KORRA.
WE HAVEN'T DECIDED IF YOU PASSED
YOUR FIREBENDING TEST YET.
- EVER SINCE YOU WERE
A LITTLE GIRL,
YOU'VE EXCELLED
AT THE PHYSICAL SIDE OF BENDING
BUT COMPLETELY IGNORED
THE SPIRITUAL SIDE.
THE AVATAR MUST MASTER BOTH.
- I HAVEN'T IGNORED IT.
IT JUST DOESN'T COME
AS EASY TO ME.
BUT THAT'S
WHY I SHOULD START TRAINING
WITH TENZIN IMMEDIATELY.
HE'S MR. SPIRITUAL.
- DO YOU BELIEVE
SHE'S READY, MASTER KATARA?
- YES.
IF ANYONE CAN TEACH HER
WHAT SHE NEEDS TO LEARN,
IT'S TENZIN.
- VERY WELL, KORRA.
IT'S TIME FOR YOU TO BEGIN
YOUR AIRBENDING TRAINING.
- YES!
FINALLY.
I MEAN...
[clears throat]
THANK YOU ALL
FOR BELIEVING IN ME.
[giggles]
NAGA, YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN IT.
I KICKED SOME FIREBENDER BUTT,
AND I PASSED.
TENZIN WILL BE HERE
IN A FEW DAYS.
[giggles]
JUST TAKING NAGA OUT
FOR A STROLL.
DON'T WORRY.
WE'RE NOT GOING FAR.
[gentle instrumental music]
NAGA, GO.
THAT A GIRL.
GO, GO, GO.
- ARE WE THERE YET?
ARE WE THERE YET?
IT LOOKS LIKE WE'RE THERE.
I KNOW
THAT THIS IS VERY FAMILIAR.
ARE WE HERE YET?
ARE WE HERE YET? ARE
WE HERE YET?
OH, PLEASE TELL ME WE'RE HERE.
- YES, IKKI,
AS I'VE BEEN TELLING YOU
FOR THE LAST 15 MINUTES,
WE ARE FINALLY HERE.
- WHEE!
- HELLO, MOTHER.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW HAPPY I AM TO SEE YOU.
PLEASE HELP ME.
- [laughs]
- UNHAND ME, STRANGE WOMAN!
- THAT'S YOUR GRANDMOTHER,
MEELO.
- IT'S SO GOOD
TO SEE ALL OF YOU.
- GRAN GRAN, I'VE BEEN READING
ALL ABOUT YOUR OLD ADVENTURES.
I'VE BEEN DYING TO ASK YOU,
WHAT HAPPENED
TO ZUKO'S MOM?
- WELL, JINORA,
IT'S AN INCREDIBLE TALE.
- GRAN GRAN, YOU LOOK OLD.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
AND WHY IS IT SO COLD
IN THE SOUTH POLE?
CAN WE MAKE A CAMPFIRE
AND ALL HUDDLE AROUND IT
AND TELL SCARY STORIES
AND MAKE SNOWMEN?
AND THEN CAN WE MAKE
THE SNOWMEN MOVE
WITH WATERBENDING
AND CHASE US?
WOULDN'T THAT BE FUN?
HUH?
WOULDN'T IT?
- PEMA, LET ME HELP YOU.
CAREFUL NOW.
CAREFUL.
- STOP DOTING ON ME.
I'M NOT HELPLESS.
I'M JUST PREGNANT.
- THE BABY'S STRONG.
I SEE ANOTHER AIRBENDER
IN YOUR FUTURE.
- ALL I WANT
IS ONE CHILD LIKE ME,
A NICE, NON-BENDER
WHO DOESN'T BLAST WIND
IN MY FACE
EVERY FIVE SECONDS.
- MOMMY, LOOK.
I'M A SNOWBENDER.
- WERE TENZIN AND HIS SIBLINGS
THIS CRAZY
WHEN THEY WERE KIDS?
- KYA AND BUMI
CERTAINLY WERE.
BUT TENZIN HAS ALWAYS BEEN
RATHER SERIOUS.
- MOTHER, PLEASE.
KORRA?
LOOK AT YOU,
SO BIG AND STRONG.
YOU'VE GROWN
INTO QUITE THE YOUNG AVATAR.
- MASTER TENZIN,
I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO GET STARTED.
- YES, WELL...
- YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO TELL HER SOONER OR LATER.
- WAIT, TELL ME WHAT?
- YOU'RE NOT STAYING,
ARE YOU?
- I'M AFRAID NOT.
WE'RE ONLY VISITING
FOR THE NIGHT.
THEN I HAVE TO RETURN
TO REPUBLIC CITY.
- BUT, NO, YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO MOVE HERE.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO TEACH ME.
- I'M SORRY, KORRA.
YOUR AIRBENDING TRAINING
IS GOING TO HAVE TO WAIT.
- SO HOW LONG UNTIL YOU'RE READY
TO TEACH ME AIRBENDING?
A WEEK?
A MONTH?
- IT COULD BE MUCH LONGER.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHY ARE YOU MAKING ME WAIT?
- I HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
TO REPUBLIC CITY.
I'M ONE OF ITS LEADERS,
AND THE SITUATION THERE
IS VERY UNSTABLE RIGHT NOW.
- BUT YOU ALSO HAVE
A RESPONSIBILITY TO TEACH ME.
BELIEVE ME, I'D BE HAPPY TO FIND
ANOTHER AIRBENDING MASTER,
BUT YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE.
WE'RE STUCK WITH EACH OTHER.
- I WISH THERE WERE ANOTHER WAY.
- WAIT.
THERE IS.
IF YOU CAN'T STAY HERE,
THEN I'LL GO BACK
TO REPUBLIC CITY
WITH YOU.
IT'S PERFECT.
- ABSOLUTELY NOT.
THE CITY IS FAR TOO DANGEROUS.
AVATAR AANG TASKED US
WITH KEEPING YOU SAFE
WHILE YOU MASTERED
THE FOUR ELEMENTS.
- I GET THAT, BUT I DON'T THINK
KEEPING ME LOCKED UP
IN THIS COMPOUND
LIKE A PRISONER
IS WHAT HE HAD IN MIND.
- I KNOW THIS IS DIFFICULT
TO ACCEPT,
BUT IT'S NOT THE RIGHT TIME
FOR YOU TO COME TO THE CITY.
- WHATEVER.
[door slams]
- GOOD-BYE, GRAN GRAN.
- OOGI, YIP YIP.
- [growls]
- [whimpers]
- NICE NIGHT FOR AN ESCAPE,
ISN'T IT?
- I HAVE TO LEAVE.
I HAVE TO FIND MY OWN PATH
AS THE AVATAR.
- I KNOW YOU DO.
AANG'S TIME HAS PASSED.
MY BROTHER AND MANY
OF MY FRIENDS ARE GONE.
IT'S TIME FOR YOU
AND YOUR GENERATION
TO TAKE ON THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF KEEPING PEACE AND BALANCE
IN THE WORLD.
AND I THINK YOU'RE GOING
TO BE A GREAT AVATAR.
- THANK YOU.
- GOOD-BYE, KORRA.
- MOM, DAD,
I'LL MISS YOU.
- WE LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
- NAGA, WE'RE HERE.
- [exclaims]
- THANKS FOR THE RIDE.
WOW.
LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
SO MANY SATO-MOBILES.
AIR TEMPLE ISLAND.
THAT'S WHERE TENZIN LIVES.
YOU READY
FOR A LITTLE SWIM, GIRL?
- [sniffs]
- OKAY, OKAY.
FOOD FIRST,
THEN AIR TEMPLE.
WATCH IT, NAGA!
LOOK OUT!
- WATCH WHERE YOU'RE GOING!
- OOPS.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
EXCUSE US.
COMING THROUGH.
HEADS UP.
SORRY.
WE'RE NEW IN TOWN.
- [sniffing]
- NAGA, WAIT.
- [whines]
- WE'LL TAKE ONE OF EVERYTHING,
PLEASE.
- THAT'LL BE 20 YUANS.
- UH, I DON'T HAVE
ANY MONEY?
- THEN WHAT GOOD ARE YOU
TO ME?
- DON'T WORRY, GIRL.
THE CITY'S HUGE.
I BET WE CAN FIND A PLACE
TO RUSTLE UP SOMETHING TO EAT.
[blows]
[gasps]
- UH, SAY,
THINK I CAN GET ONE
OF THEM TASTY-SMELLING FISHIES?
- OH, UH,
YEAH, SURE.
- [hums]
- SO DO YOU LIVE
IN THAT BUSH?
- YES, PRESENTLY
THAT IS WHAT I DO CALL HOME.
TOOK ME A WHILE TO PROCURE
A BUSH THAT BEAUTEOUS.
THIS PARK IS QUITE POPULAR
WITH ALL THE VAGABONDS.
- SO THERE ARE A LOT OF YOU
OUT HERE?
I THOUGHT EVERYONE IN THIS CITY
WAS LIVING IT UP.
- [laughs]
YOU GOT A LOT TO LEARN,
NEWCOMER.
WELCOME TO REPUBLIC CITY.
[whistle blowing]
- HEY, YOU, STOP.
YOU CAN'T FISH HERE.
- YOU BEST SKEDADDLE.
WOO!
- [whistles]
- [blows whistle]
[pants]
- ARE YOU TIRED
OF LIVING UNDER THE TYRANNY
OF BENDERS?
THEN JOIN THE EQUALISTS.
FOR TOO LONG,
THE BENDING ELITE
OF THIS CITY
HAVE FORCED NON-BENDERS
TO LIVE AS LOWER-CLASS CITIZENS.
JOIN AMON, AND TOGETHER
WE WILL TEAR DOWN
THE BENDING ESTABLISHMENT.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
BENDING IS THE COOLEST THING
IN THE WORLD.
- OH, YEAH?
LET ME GUESS.
YOU'RE A BENDER.
- YEAH, I AM.
- AND I BET YOU'D JUST LOVE
TO KNOCK ME
OFF THIS PLATFORM
WITH SOME WATERBENDING, HUH?
- I'M SERIOUSLY THINKING
ABOUT IT.
- THIS IS WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THE CITY.
BENDERS LIKE THIS GIRL
ONLY USE THEIR POWER
TO OPPRESS US.
[all shouting]
- WHAT?
I'M NOT OPPRESSING ANYONE.
YOU'RE...
YOU'RE OPPRESSING YOURSELF.
- THAT DIDN'T EVEN MAKE SENSE.
- EXCUSE ME.
I THINK I'M LOST.
HOW DO I GET
TO AIR TEMPLE ISLAND FROM HERE?
- JUST HEAD DOWN THIS STREET.
YOU SHOULD GET MOVING,
YOUNG LADY.
IT ISN'T SAFE.
- MR. CHUNG, PLEASE TELL ME
THAT YOU HAVE MY MONEY.
OR ELSE I CAN'T GUARANTEE
I CAN PROTECT
YOUR FINE ESTABLISHMENT.
- I'M SORRY.
BUSINESS HAS BEEN SLOW.
PLEASE TAKE ONE
OF MY PHONOGRAPHS.
[shouts]
- MY FRIEND HERE
IS NOT A MUSIC LOVER.
GIVE ME THE MONEY OR ELSE--
- OR ELSE WHAT, HOODLUM?
[laughter]
- SINCE YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY FRESH
OFF THE BOAT,
LET ME EXPLAIN
A COUPLE THINGS.
YOU'RE IN TRIPLE THREAT TRIAD
TERRITORY,
AND WE'RE ABOUT TO PUT YOU
IN THE HOSPITAL.
- YOU'RE THE ONLY ONES
WHO ARE GONNA NEED
A HOSPITAL.
AND, FOR YOUR SAKE,
I HOPE
THERE'S ONE NEARBY.
- WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
- WHY DON'T YOU COME
AND FIND OUT?
- [exclaims]
[grunts]
- HAA!
OOH!
- WHAT JUST HAPPENED?
- DID SHE JUST EARTHBEND?
- [grunting]
- [grunts]
YAA!
AAGH!
- CAN SHE FIREBEND TOO?
- COULD SHE BE...
- [straining]
- [grunts]
- [chuckles]
GOT AN IDEA ABOUT WHO I AM NOW,
CHUMPS?
- COME ON.
- AAGH!
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING AWAY.
[gangsters groaning]
[police sirens wailing]
- POLICE.
FREEZE WHERE YOU ARE.
- COOL.
METALBENDERS.
I CAUGHT THE BAD GUYS
FOR YOU, OFFICERS.
- ARREST THEM.
[gangsters groaning]
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST TOO.
- [gasps]
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN
I'M UNDER ARREST?
THOSE ARE THE BAD GUYS
OVER THERE.
THEY WERE SMASHING UP A SHOP.
- FROM THE LOOKS OF IT,
YOU SMASHED UP A LOT MORE
THAN THAT.
- WAIT. YOU CAN'T ARREST ME.
LET ME EXPLAIN.
- YOU CAN EXPLAIN YOURSELF
ALL YOU LIKE
DOWN AT HEADQUARTERS.
[grunts]
- [grunts]
[crash]
[exclamations]
- [exclaims]
- [shouts, grunts]
- HEY!
- [exhales]
[sirens wail]
[straining]
[Naga whimpers]
- LET'S SEE.
MULTIPLE COUNTS
OF DESTRUCTION
OF PRIVATE
AND CITY PROPERTY,
NOT TO MENTION
EVADING ARREST.
YOU'RE IN A WHOLE MESS
OF TROUBLE, YOUNG LADY.
- BUT THERE WERE SOME THUGS
THREATENING
A HELPLESS SHOPKEEPER AND I--
- CAN IT.
YOU SHOULD HAVE CALLED
THE POLICE
AND STAYED OUT OF THE WAY.
- BUT I COULDN'T JUST SIT BY
AND DO NOTHING.
IT'S MY DUTY
TO HELP PEOPLE.
SEE, I'M THE AVATAR.
- OH, I AM WELL AWARE
OF WHO YOU ARE,
AND YOUR AVATAR TITLE
MIGHT IMPRESS SOME PEOPLE,
BUT NOT ME.
- ALL RIGHT.
FINE.
THEN I WANT TO TALK
TO WHOEVER'S IN CHARGE.
- YOU'RE TALKING TO HER.
I'M CHIEF BEIFONG.
- WAIT.
BEIFONG?
LIN BEIFONG?
YOU'RE TOPH'S DAUGHTER.
- WHAT OF IT?
- WELL, THEN, WHY ARE YOU
TREATING ME LIKE A CRIMINAL?
AVATAR AANG AND YOUR MOTHER
WERE FRIENDS.
THEY SAVED THE WORLD TOGETHER.
- THAT'S ANCIENT HISTORY.
AND IT'S GOT DIDDLY SQUAT
TO DO WITH THE MESS
YOU ARE IN RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN'T JUST WALTZ IN HERE
AND DOLE OUT VIGILANTE JUSTICE
LIKE YOU OWN THE PLACE.
- CHIEF, COUNCILMAN TENZIN
IS HERE.
- LET HIM IN.
- TENZIN.
SORRY.
I GOT A LITTLE SIDETRACKED
ON MY WAY TO SEE YOU.
- [inhales]
LIN, YOU ARE LOOKING RADIANT
AS USUAL.
- CUT THE GARBAGE, TENZIN.
WHY IS THE AVATAR
IN REPUBLIC CITY?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO BE MOVING DOWN
TO THE SOUTH POLE
TO TRAIN HER.
- MY RELOCATION
HAS BEEN DELAYED.
THE AVATAR,
ON THE OTHER HAND,
WILL BE HEADING BACK
TO THE SOUTH POLE IMMEDIATELY,
WHERE SHE WILL STAY PUT.
- BUT--
- IF YOU WOULD BE SO KIND
AS TO DROP THE CHARGES
AGAINST KORRA,
I WILL TAKE FULL RESPONSIBILITY
FOR TODAY'S REGRETTABLE EVENTS
AND COVER ALL THE DAMAGES.
- FINE.
GET HER OUT OF MY CITY.
- ALWAYS A PLEASURE, LIN.
LET'S GO, KORRA.
- HMM.
- TENZIN, PLEASE,
DON'T SEND ME BACK HOME.
- YOU BLATANTLY DISOBEYED
MY WISHES
AND THE ORDERS
OF THE WHITE LOTUS.
- KATARA AGREED WITH ME
THAT I SHOULD COME.
SHE SAID MY DESTINY
IS IN REPUBLIC CITY.
- DON'T BRING MY MOTHER
INTO THIS!
- LOOK, I CAN'T WAIT
ANY LONGER
TO FINISH MY TRAINING.
BEING COOPED UP
AND HIDDEN AWAY
FROM THE WORLD
ISN'T HELPING ME
BECOME A BETTER AVATAR.
I SAW A LOT OF THE CITY TODAY,
AND IT'S TOTALLY OUT OF WHACK.
I UNDERSTAND NOW
WHY YOU NEED TO STAY.
REPUBLIC CITY DOES NEED YOU,
BUT IT NEEDS ME TOO.
- [stammers]
[sighs]
- IS THIS YOUR POLAR BEAR DOG,
MISS?
all: KORRA!
- ARE YOU COMING TO LIVE WITH US
ON THE ISLAND?
- NO.
I'M SORRY, IKKI.
I HAVE TO GO HOME NOW.
- AW.
- WAIT.
I HAVE DONE MY BEST
TO GUIDE REPUBLIC CITY
TOWARDS THE DREAM
MY FATHER HAD FOR IT.
BUT YOU ARE RIGHT.
IT HAS FALLEN OUT OF BALANCE
SINCE HE PASSED.
I THOUGHT I SHOULD PUT OFF
YOUR TRAINING
IN ORDER TO UPHOLD HIS LEGACY,
BUT YOU ARE HIS LEGACY.
YOU MAY STAY AND TRAIN
AIRBENDING HERE WITH ME.
- [gasps]
- REPUBLIC CITY
NEEDS ITS AVATAR ONCE AGAIN.
- YES!
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE THE BEST.
all: YAY!
- [giggles]
- [loving sigh]
- [sighs]
[cheers and applause]
- [clears throat]
HELLO, I'M KORRA,
YOUR NEW AVATAR.
- DOES THIS MEAN YOU'VE MOVED
TO REPUBLIC CITY?
- WERE YOU TRYING TO SEND A
MESSAGE TO THE TRIADS YESTERDAY?
- WILL YOU BE FIGHTING CRIME
OR THE ANTI-BENDING REVOLUTION
OR BOTH?
- WILL YOU BE WORKING WITH
CHIEF BEIFONG AND THE POLICE?
- UH, YES, I AM DEFINITELY HERE
TO STAY,
BUT, HONESTLY, I-I DON'T EXACTLY
HAVE A PLAN YET.
SEE,
I'M STILL IN TRAINING,
BUT, LOOK, ALL I KNOW
IS AVATAR AANG
MEANT FOR THIS CITY
TO BE THE CENTER
OF PEACE AND BALANCE
IN THE WORLD.
AND I BELIEVE
WE CAN MAKE HIS DREAM A REALITY.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO SERVING YOU.
I'M SO HAPPY TO BE HERE.
THANK YOU, REPUBLIC CITY.
- ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL THE QUESTIONS THE--
- AMON, HOW DO YOU WANT
TO HANDLE THIS?
- SO THE AVATAR
HAS ARRIVED EARLY.
IT LOOKS LIKE WE'LL HAVE
TO ACCELERATE OUR PLANS.