male announcer:
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- REPUBLIC CITY WELCOMES
A NEW CITIZEN INTO HER ARMS,
AVATAR KORRA.
AFTER YEARS OF SECLUSION
IN THE SOUTH,
THIS MASTER OF WATER,
EARTH, AND FIRE,
SEEKS TO ADD AIRBENDING
TO HER LIST OF SKILLS.
AND UNDER THE TUTELAGE
OF TENZIN,
AVATAR AANG'S SON,
SHE SHOULD GO FAR.
BUT WILL THIS COOL,
CALM, COLLECTED
MASTER OF AIR BE ABLE
TO TAME THIS HOTHEADED TEEN?
[flute music]
♪ ♪
[growling]
- AND IN THE FINAL ROUND,
THE BUZZARD-WASPS
WON WITH A DECISIVE KNOCKOUT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GO TO THE ARENA TONIGHT,
CATCH A FEW PRO BENDING
MATCHES?
- THAT SPORT IS A MOCKERY
OF THE NOBLE TRADITION
OF BENDING.
- COME ON, TENZIN,
I'VE DREAMED ABOUT
SEEING A PRO BENDING MATCH
SINCE I WAS A KID,
AND NOW I'M JUST A FERRY RIDE
AWAY FROM THE ARENA.
- KORRA, YOU'RE NOT HERE
TO WATCH THAT DRIVEL.
YOU'RE HERE TO FINISH
YOUR AVATAR TRAINING.
SO FOR THE TIME BEING,
I WANT YOU TO REMAIN
ON THE ISLAND.
- IS THAT WHY YOU'RE KEEPING
THE WHITE LOTUS SENTRIES
AROUND TO WATCH
MY EVERY MOVE?
- YES, IN ORDER
TO LEARN AIRBENDING,
I BELIEVE YOU REQUIRE
A CALM, QUIET ENVIRONMENT,
FREE FROM ANY DISTRACTIONS.
- ALL RIGHT,
YOU'RE THE MASTER.
[bird chirps]
- SO MY MOTHER
INFORMED ME THAT
YOU'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE
TO AIRBEND BEFORE.
- [sighs]
YEAH, BUT I DON'T KNOW WHY.
THE OTHER ELEMENTS
CAME SO EASILY TO ME.
BUT EVERY SINGLE TIME
I'VE TRIED AIRBENDING--
[raspberries]
NOTHING.
- THAT'S PERFECTLY
ALL RIGHT.
WE JUST NEED
TO BE PATIENT.
OFTEN THE ELEMENT
THAT'S THE MOST DIFFICULT
FOR THE AVATAR TO MASTER
IS THE ONE MOST OPPOSITE
TO THE AVATAR'S PERSONALITY.
FOR AANG,
IT WAS EARTHBENDING.
- YEAH, WELL, I'M ABOUT
AS OPPOSITE AN AIRBENDER
AS YOU CAN GET.
- LET'S BEGIN
YOUR FIRST LESSON.
- KORRA'S GONNA AIRBEND!
KORRA'S GONNA AIRBEND!
- WHAT IS THAT CONTRAPTION?
- A TIME-HONORED TOOL
THAT TEACHES
THE MOST FUNDAMENTAL ASPECT
OF AIRBENDING.
JINORA, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO EXPLAIN THIS EXERCISE?
- THE GOAL IS TO WEAVE
YOUR WAY THROUGH THE GATES
AND MAKE IT TO THE OTHER SIDE
WITHOUT TOUCHING THEM.
- SEEMS EASY ENOUGH.
- JINORA FORGOT TO SAY
YOU HAVE TO MAKE IT THROUGH
WHILE THE GATES ARE SPINNING.
[wind blows]
- THE KEY IS TO BE
LIKE THE LEAF.
FLOW WITH THE MOVEMENT
OF THE GATES.
JINORA WILL DEMONSTRATE.
AIRBENDING IS ALL ABOUT
SPIRAL MOVEMENTS.
WHEN YOU MEET RESISTANCE,
YOU MUST BE ABLE
TO SWITCH DIRECTION
AT A MOMENT'S NOTICE.
[wind blows]
- LET'S DO THIS.
[grunting]
AAH!
[groans]
[grunting]
- DON'T FORCE
YOUR WAY THROUGH.
- DANCE,
DANCE LIKE THE WIND.
- BE THE LEAF.
- AAH!
[birds chirping]
[groans]
- [sighs]
- AIRBEND.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH ME?
AIRBEND!
[growls]
[grunts]
UGH.
MAYBE I'M JUST NOT
CUT OUT TO BE AN AIRBENDER,
HUH, NAGA?
- LADIES AND GENTLEMAN,
I'M COMING TO YOU LIVE
FROM REPUBLIC CITY'S
PRO BENDING ARENA,
WHERE TONIGHT,
THE BEST IN THE WORLD
CONTINUE THEIR QUEST
FOR A SPOT IN THE UPCOMING
CHAMPIONSHIP TOURNAMENT.
GRABS YOUR SNACKS
AND GRAB YOUR KIDS
BECAUSE THIS NEXT MATCH
IS GONNA BE A DOOZY.
THIS MAKO'S GOT MOXIE.
HE ADVANCES,
FIRES TWO QUICK SHOTS.
YOMO IS HAMMERED BACK
TO ZONE THREE.
CLOCK IS WINDING DOWN,
CAN YOMO HOLD ON?
HE'S TEETERING ON THE EDGE
OF THE RING NOW.
THE FIRE FERRETS LINE UP
TO STRIKE--
- KORRA, COME DOWN HERE
PLEASE.
- YOU SHUT IT OFF
AT THE BEST PART.
- I THOUGHT
I MADE MYSELF CLEAR.
I DON'T WANT YOU LISTENING
TO THIS DISTRACTING NONSENSE.
- BUT IT'S THEIR RADIO.
AND TECHNICALLY, YOU SAID
I COULDN'T WATCH A MATCH.
YOU DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT LISTENING TO ONE.
- YOU--
[groans]
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEANT.
ANYWAY, SHOULDN'T YOU--
SHOULDN'T YOU BE
IN BED BY NOW?
[growling]
[sniffing]
- I THINK
I'M DOING IT WRONG.
- THERE'S NOTHING TO DO.
LET YOUR MIND
AND YOUR SPIRIT BE FREE,
FOR AIR IS THE ELEMENT
OF FREEDOM.
- [laughs]
- IS SOMETHING FUNNY?
- YEAH, YOU'RE TELLING ME
TO EMBRACE FREEDOM,
BUT YOU WON'T EVEN
LET ME LISTEN TO THE RADIO.
AND FORGET ABOUT
LEAVING THIS ISLAND.
- PLEASE, KORRA.
LOOK AT MEELO.
HE'S ABLE TO MEDITATE
PEACEFULLY.
- [snoring]
- ACTUALLY, I THINK
HE'S ASLEEP.
- WHAT?
WELL, AT LEAST HE HAS
THE RELAXING PART DOWN.
- WHATEVER.
NONE OF THIS AIRBENDING STUFF
MAKES ANY SENSE TO ME.
- I KNOW YOU'RE FRUSTRATED,
BUT THESE TEACHINGS
WILL SINK IN OVER TIME.
THEN, ONE DAY,
THEY'LL JUST CLICK.
- [inhales]
YEAH, IT'S NOT
SINKING IN YET.
I'M GONNA GO GET
A GLASS OF LYCHEE JUICE.
- KORRA, THE MEDITATION'S
NOT OVER YET.
- DADDY, CAN I HAVE
SOME LYCHEE JUICE TOO?
- NO.
- [groans]
- [panting]
- HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN MY GYM?
- UH, I WAS JUST LOOKING
FOR A BATHROOM,
AND I GOT LOST.
- AH, THE OLD
"I HAD TO PEE" EXCUSE.
YOU KNOW, I'M SICK
AND TIRED OF YOU KIDS
SNEAKING IN WITHOUT PAYING.
I'M TAKING YOU
TO SECURITY.
- NO, WAIT.
- THERE YOU ARE.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
EVERYWHERE FOR YOU.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, TOZA.
SHE'S WITH ME.
- YEAH, I'M WITH HIM.
- SO, YOU SEE,
WE'RE TOGETHER.
- WELL, NOT TOGETHER
TOGETHER.
MORE LIKE FRIENDS.
- RIGHT, FRIENDS.
NO, NO, I DIDN'T
MEAN TO IMPLY--
- OH, YOU IMPLIED IT.
- I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU ARE.
I GOT WORK TO DO.
- RIGHT THIS WAY, MISS.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
SERIOUSLY, THANKS.
[crowd cheering]
- WHAT DO YOU THINK?
BEST SEATS IN THE HOUSE, HUH?
- WHOA.
UNBELIEVABLE.
THIS PLACE IS EVEN
MORE AMAZING THAN I IMAGINED.
- NAME'S BOLIN,
BY THE WAY.
- KORRA.
- PSST, BOLIN.
- YEAH.
- I TOLD YOU,
YOU HAVE TO STOP
BRINGING YOUR CRAZY
FAN GIRLS IN HERE
BEFORE THE MATCHES.
GET HER OUT OF HERE.
- AW, COME ON, MAKO.
ALL RIGHT, LOOK, I KIND OF
PROMISED HER SHE COULD STAY.
BUT, MAN, I GOT
A GOOD FEELING.
THERE'S SOMETHING
SPECIAL ABOUT HER.
I KNOW IT.
COME HERE, I WANT YOU
TO MEET MY BROTHER MAKO.
- MAKO?
WOW, I HEARD YOU PLAY
ON THE RADIO.
- COME ON, BOLIN,
WE'RE UP.
- OR I COULD MEET HIM LATER.
- YEAH, SORRY ABOUT THAT.
MY BROTHER JUST GETS
REAL FOCUSED BEFORE A MATCH.
OKAY, I GOTTA GO.
WISH ME LUCK.
NOT THAT I'LL NEED IT.
- [chuckles]
GOOD LUCK.
KNOCK THEM OUT!
- INTRODUCING
THE FIRE FERRETS.
- AHH!
I LOVE YOU, BOLIN!
- THE ROOKIE FERRETS
CAME FROM OUT OF NOWHERE
AND HAVE MADE IT FURTHER
THAN ANYONE
EXPECTED THIS SEASON.
BUT TONIGHT THEY FACE
THEIR TOUGHEST TEST YET, FOLKS.
AND THEY'RE OFF.
THE TWO TEAMS
WASTE NO TIME TRYING
TO BLAST EACH OTHER
OUT OF ZONE ONE.
HASOOK IS THE FIRST
TO FEEL THE HEAT
OF THE TIGER-DILLOS.
HE TRIES TO RETURN
THE FAVOR,
BUT THEY'RE TOO FAST
FOR HIM.
WHILE MAKO SHOWCASES
HIS TRADEMARK
"COOL UNDER FIRE" STYLE.
- AAH!
- OH, THE TIGER-DILLOS SCORE
WITH A WALLOPING
ONE-TWO COMBO.
CAN THEIR TEAMMATE HOLD ON
TO THEIR ZONE ONE TERRITORY?
- [grunts]
[buzzer sounds]
- GUESS NOT.
MAKO'S OVER THE LINE.
THE TIGER-DILLOS GET
THE GREEN LIGHT
AND ADVANCE INTO
FERRET TERRITORY.
- COME ON, FERRETS!
- [grunts]
- LOOKS LIKE
HASOOK'S IN TROUBLE.
HE'S IN ZONE THREE,
TEETERING OVER THE DRINK.
- AAH!
- AND HASOOK TAKES A DIP.
HE'LL BE BACK FOR ROUND TWO,
ASSUMING THE FABULOUS
BENDING BROTHERS
CAN HOLD THEIR GROUND
UNTIL THE NEXT ROUND.
[buzzer sounds]
[bell rings]
- ROUND ONE GOES
TO THE GOLDEN TEMPLE
TIGER-DILLOS.
- COME ON, HASOOK,
GET YOUR ACT TOGETHER.
[buzzer sounds]
- THE FIRE FERRETS
ARE KNOCKED INTO ZONE TWO,
AND THE TIGER-DILLOS
ADVANCE.
- [grunts]
[buzzer sounds]
[bell rings]
THE FIRE FERRETS
CINCH THE ROUND
IN THE CLOSING SECONDS.
IT'S ONE APIECE,
STILL ANYONE'S MATCH
AS WE GOT INTO
THE THIRD AND FINAL ROUND.
[bell rings]
HASOOK STUMBLES,
AND NOW HE TUMBLES
RIGHT INTO HIS TEAMMATE.
HE AND BOLIN BETTER
UNTANGLE QUICK
IF THEY DON'T WANT TO--
OH, TOO LATE!
- OH, NO.
- IT'S ALL UP TO MAKO NOW.
HE'S BOBBING AND WEAVING.
HE'S WEAVING AND BOBBING.
BUT HE'S NOT HITTING BACK.
IF MAKO'S KNOCKED OUT,
THE FERRETS'
FABULOUS SEASON IS OVER.
HE DANCING
ON THE EDGE OF THE RING,
SURVIVING
THE THREE-ON-ONE BARRAGE.
IT SEEMS HIS PLAN
IS TO LET THE TIGER-DILLOS
PUNCH THEMSELVES OUT.
AND HIS PLAN IS WORKING.
HAHN IS IN THE POOL.
THEY'VE GOT NOTHING
LEFT IN THE TANK,
AND MAKO IS ON THE OFFENSIVE.
IT'S TWO-ON-ONE.
SCRATCH THAT,
IT'S ONE-ON-ONE.
AND IT'S AN EARTH AND FIRE
SLUGFEST.
THERE'S SO MUCH SMOKE
AND DUST FROM THE FIRE FIGHT,
I CAN'T EVEN SEE
WHERE THE FIRE FERRET IS.
[cheers and applause]
- IT'S A KNOCKOUT!
WHAT A WINGDINGER
OF A HAT TRICK, FOLKS.
MAKO PULLS OFF
THE UPSET OF THE SEASON,
WINNING THE MATCH
FOR THE FIRE FERRETS.
[cheers and applause]
- WHOO-HOO! YES!
ONE MORE WIN AND WE'RE IN
THE CHAMPIONSHIP TOURNAMENT.
[snaps]
SO WHAT'D YOU THINK, KORRA?
BOLIN'S GOT
SOME MOVES, HUH?
- WHAT DID I THINK?
WHAT DID I THINK?
THAT WAS AMAZING.
- YOU DID MORE HARM
THAN GOOD OUT THERE.
YOU ALMOST COST US
THE MATCH.
- WE WON, DIDN'T WE?
- BARELY.
- GET OFF MY CASE, PAL.
UGH.
- USELESS.
- YOU GUYS WERE INCREDIBLE
OUT THERE.
ESPECIALLY YOU,
MR. HAT TRICK.
- OH, YOU'RE STILL HERE?
- OH, YOU'RE STILL A JERK?
- OOH.
- ANYWAY...
I'VE BEEN IMMERSED
IN BENDING MY ENTIRE LIFE,
BUT I NEVER LEARNED
HOW TO MOVE LIKE THAT.
IT'S LIKE THERE'S
A WHOLE NEW STYLE HERE.
THINK YOU COULD SHOW ME
A FEW TRICKS?
- ABSOLUTELY.
- RIGHT NOW?
COME ON, BOLIN.
- JUST IGNORE HIM.
YEAH, I COULD SHOW YOU
THE BASICS.
I'M JUST NOT SURE
HOW MY EARTHBENDING
WOULD TRANSLATE
TO YOUR WATERBENDING,
BUT WE'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
- WON'T BE A PROBLEM.
I'M ACTUALLY
AN EARTHBENDER.
- I'M SORRY, NO, NO,
I DIDN'T MEAN TO ASSUME.
'CAUSE I--YOU KNOW,
I WAS JUST FIGURING--
WITH YOUR WATER TRIBE GETUP,
THAT YOU ARE
A WATER TRIBE GAL.
- NOPE, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M A WATERBENDER.
AND A FIREBENDER.
- MM. MM-HMM.
I'M VERY CONFUSED
RIGHT NOW.
- YOU'RE THE AVATAR,
AND I'M AN IDIOT.
- BOTH ARE TRUE.
- NO WAY.
THE AVATAR!
ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU GOT.
THAT WAS GREAT.
GOOD POWER.
BUT, IN A REAL MATCH,
YOU'D BE
A SITTING TURTLE-DUCK.
NOT SO UPRIGHT
AND FLAT-FOOTED.
STAY LIGHT ON YOUR TOES,
RIGHT UP UNTIL THE MOMENT
WHEN YOU NEED TO DIG IN
AND STRIKE.
THEN--
POP! POP!
- OKAY, LET ME
TRY IT AGAIN.
- WOW!
NICE ADJUSTMENT.
YOU'RE A NATURAL AT THIS.
- NOT BAD.
- WHAT'S IT TAKE
TO IMPRESS THIS GUY?
- WHAT?
I SAID, "NOT BAD."
YOU KNOW WHAT,
IT'S GETTING LATE.
I THINK I'M GONNA TURN IN.
YOU KIDS HAVE FUN.
NICE TO MEET YOU,
AVATAR KORRA.
- YEAH, BEEN A REAL PLEASURE.
- SEE YOU UPSTAIRS, BRO.
- UPSTAIRS?
YOU GUYS LIVE HERE?
- YEP.
IN THE ATTIC.
IT'S NOTHING FANCY,
BUT WE HAVE SOME GREAT VIEWS.
SO BACK TO BENDING.
WHY DON'T YOU THROW
THAT COMBO ONE MORE TIME?
- AAH!
[grunting]
- PATIENCE, KORRA.
- [grunting]
[yelling]
- THAT WAS A 2,000-YEAR-OLD
HISTORICAL TREASURE.
WHAT--
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
- THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH ME.
I'VE BEEN PRACTICING,
JUST LIKE YOU TAUGHT ME.
BUT IT ISN'T
SINKING IN, OKAY?
IT HASN'T CLICKED
LIKE YOU SAID IT WOULD.
- KORRA, THIS ISN'T
SOMETHING YOU CAN FORCE.
IF YOU WOULD ONLY
LISTEN TO ME.
- I HAVE BEEN.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I THINK?
MAYBE THE PROBLEM ISN'T ME.
MAYBE THE REASON I HAVEN'T
LEARNED AIRBENDING YET
IS BECAUSE YOU'RE
A TERRIBLE TEACHER.
- [grunts]
- YEAH, YOU'RE
A TERRIBLE TEACHER, DADDY.
WAH!
AAH!
- OKAY, EVERYONE HERE?
WAIT, WHERE'S KORRA?
- HONESTLY, PEMA, I AM AT
MY WIT'S END WITH THAT GIRL.
I--I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO GET THROUGH TO HER.
- DEAR, THE BEST THING
YOU CAN DO RIGHT NOW
IS TO GIVE KORRA SOME SPACE.
- YOU MUST PROMISE ME
THAT YOUR TEENAGE YEARS
WON'T BE LIKE THIS.
- I WILL MAKE
NO SUCH PROMISES.
- I DIDN'T MISS YOUR MATCH,
DID I?
YOU GUYS LOOK LIKE
YOU LOST ALREADY.
- WE MIGHT AS WELL HAVE.
- HASOOK'S A NO-GOOD
NO-SHOW.
- YOU GOT TWO MINUTES
TO COME OUT READY TO PLAY,
OR YOU'RE DISQUALIFIED.
- WELL, THERE GOES OUR SHOT
AT THE TOURNAMENT...
AND THE WINNINGS.
- CAN'T YOU ASK
ONE OF THOSE GUYS TO FILL IN?
- NO, THE RULES SAY YOU CAN
ONLY COMPETE ON ONE TEAM.
- WELL, THEN...
HOW ABOUT ME?
I'M A TOP-NOTCH WATERBENDER,
IF I DO SAY SO MYSELF.
- BUT YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
ISN'T THAT CHEATING?
- IT ISN'T CHEATING
IF I ONLY DO WATERBENDING.
- NO WAY,
I'D RATHER FORFEIT
THAN LOOK LIKE
A FOOL OUT THERE.
- WOW, THANKS FOR THE VOTE
OF CONFIDENCE.
- TIME'S UP,
YOU IN OR OUT?
- WE'RE IN.
- WE ARE?
- YES!
- HEY, I DIDN'T AGREE TO THIS.
- YOU CAN THANK ME LATER.
- THIS GIRL IS CRAZY.
- LOOKS LIKE THE FIRE FERRETS
HAVE FERRETED OUT
A LAST-MINUTE
REPLACEMENT WATERBENDER.
LET'S SEE IF SHE'S ANOTHER
DIAMOND IN THE ROUGH,
LIKE THE BROTHERS FROM
THE SCHOOL OF HARD KNOCKS.
- DON'T DO ANYTHING
TOO FANCY OR AGGRESSIVE.
IN FACT, DON'T DO ANYTHING.
JUST TRY NOT TO GET
KNOCKED OFF THE RING.
- YOU GOT IT, CAPTAIN.
- PLAYERS, ARE YOU READY?
[whistle blows]
[bell rings]
- AAH!
[splashes]
- WHOO-HOO!
MAN OVERBOARD.
- FIRE FERRET WATERBENDER,
PENALTY.
MOVE BACK ONE ZONE.
- WHAT?
WHY?
- YOU'RE ONLY ALLOWED
TO KNOCK PLAYERS
OFF THE BACK OF THE RING,
NOT OVER THE SIDES.
- OH, WHOOPS.
[bell rings]
- AND WE'RE BACK IN ACTION
AFTER THAT HICCUP.
BUT I'M NOT SO SURE
THIS REPLACEMENT PLAYER
KNOWS WHAT SHE'S DOING.
[buzzer sounds]
- FOUL, OVER THE LINE.
MOVE BACK TO ZONE THREE.
- I'LL SHOW YOU
OVER THE LINE.
[audience booing]
[bell rings]
- THE PLATYPUS-BEARS
TAKE ROUND ONE.
THE PLATYPUS-BEARS
KNOW A GREEN PLAYER
WHEN THEY SEE ONE.
AND THEY ARE FOCUSING
THE BRUNT OF THEIR BENDING
ON THIS POOR GIRL.
- [growls]
- WAIT A MINUTE, DID THAT
WATERBENDER JUST EARTHBEND?
[gasping]
[whistle blows]
- FOUL, I THINK.
- [chuckles]
- DID I SEE THAT RIGHT?
- [sighs]
- HOLD ON, FOLKS,
WE'RE JUST WAITING
FOR THE REFEREES'
OFFICIAL CALL,
BUT I THINK THIS
REPLACEMENT PLAYER COULD BE--
- PARDON ME, EVERYONE,
HAVE YOU SEEN
KORRA THIS EVENING?
SHE'S NOT IN HER ROOM.
- YOU'VE GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
SHE'S THE AVATAR, FOLKS!
PLAYING IN
A PRO BENDING MATCH.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
- I'LL GET HER MYSELF.
- THE AVATAR WILL BE
PERMITTED TO CONTINUE,
SO LONG AS SHE SOLELY
BENDS WATER.
all: AWW.
[bell rings]
- THIS GIRL MAY BE
THE AVATAR,
BUT SHE'S NO PRO BENDER.
AND THE PLATYPUS-BEARS
ARE INTENT
ON EXPLOITING THAT WEAKNESS.
THEY'RE GIVING HER
THEIR BEST,
AND HER BEST AIN'T GOOD ENOUGH
TO STOP IT.
[buzzer sounds]
AND SHE'S IN THE DRINK.
- [grunts]
OH, HEY, TENZIN.
I THOUGHT YOU DIDN'T
LIKE COMING TO THESE MATCHES.
- ONCE AGAIN,
YOU HAVE FLAGRANTLY
DISOBEYED MY ORDERS.
YOU WERE TO STAY
ON THE ISLAND.
LET'S GO.
- NO.
I'M KIND OF IN THE MIDDLE
OF SOMETHING.
- I HAVE TRIED MY VERY BEST
TO GET THROUGH TO YOU
BY BEING GENTLE AND PATIENT,
BUT CLEARLY THE ONLY THING
YOU RESPOND TO IS FORCE.
SO I AM ORDERING YOU TO COME
BACK TO THE TEMPLE RIGHT NOW.
- WHY?
SO I CAN SIT AROUND
AND MEDITATE
ABOUT HOW BAD I AM
AT AIRBENDING?
YOU KNOW, I'M BEGINNING
TO THINK THERE'S A REASON
I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO LEARN IT.
BECAUSE MAYBE I DON'T
EVEN NEED IT!
- WHAT?
THAT IS
A LUDICROUS SUGGESTION.
THE AVATAR NEEDS
TO LEARN AIRBENDING.
IT IS NOT OPTIONAL.
- NO, THIS IS WHAT
I NEED TO LEARN.
MODERN STYLES OF FIGHTING.
- BEING THE AVATAR ISN'T
ALL ABOUT FIGHTING, KORRA.
WHEN WILL YOU LEARN THAT?
- I HAVE A MATCH
TO GO FINISH.
[bell rings]
- THE PLATYPUS-BEARS
WIN ROUND TWO.
ROUND THREE.
- THE PLATYPUS-BEARS
COME OUT OF THE GATE
AND QUICKLY GO AFTER
THE FERRET BROTHERS.
THEY'RE CORRALLED
IN THE CORNER,
WEDGED IN THE EDGE
OF ZONE ONE,
UNABLE TO COME
TO THE AVATAR'S RESCUE.
AND, BOY,
DOES SHE NEED IT.
[cheers and applause]
- [grunts]
- LOOKS LIKE THE AVATAR'S
PRO BENDING DEBUT
IS GOING TO BE CUT SHORT.
- UGH.
- SHE'S BEEN PUSHED BACK
TO ZONE THREE,
AND THE WATER
IS CALLING HER NAME.
IT'S ONLY A MATTER
OF TIME BEFORE--
HOLD THE PHONE.
STOP THE PRESSES.
SHE'S STILL
IN THE GAME, FOLKS.
AND SHE'S MOVING LIKE
AN ENTIRELY DIFFERENT PLAYER.
ALL OFF A SUDDEN,
THE PLATYPUS-BEAR STRIKES
ARE ONLY STRIKING AIR.
- HOW ABOUT THAT?
- THE PLATYPUS-BEARS
HAVE NO JUICE LEFT,
BUT MAKO AND BOLIN
ARE STILL FRESH AND JUICY.
- [grunting]
[buzzer sounds]
- AAH!
[bell rings]
- KNOCKOUT.
- WHOO-HOO!
- THE FIRE FERRETS
COME FROM WAY BEHIND
AND STEAL THE WIN.
WHAT AN UPSET, FOLKS.
THE ROOKIES, AVATAR IN TOW,
HAVE NABBED A PLACE
IN THE CHAMPIONSHIP
TOURNAMENT.
I CANNOT BELIEVE IT.
[laughter]
- YES!
- YEAH!
- KORRA, WHAT CAN I SAY?
YOU REALLY CAME ALIVE
IN THAT LAST ROUND.
THE WAY YOU DODGED
THEIR ATTACKS--
YOU ARE A NATURAL.
- THANKS, BUT I CAN'T
TAKE ALL THE CREDIT.
SOMEONE ELSE TAUGHT ME
THOSE MOVES.
I'M REALLY SORRY...
ABOUT EVERYTHING I SAID.
I WAS REALLY
FRUSTRATED WITH MYSELF,
AND I TOOK IT OUT ON YOU.
- I THINK I OWE YOU
AN APOLOGY TOO.
I WAS TRYING TO TEACH YOU
ABOUT PATIENCE,
BUT I LOST MINE.
- NO HARD FEELINGS?
- OF COURSE NOT.
BY THE WAY, YOU WERE REALLY
GOOD OUT THERE TONIGHT.
YOU MOVED JUST LIKE
AN AIRBENDER.
- WAIT, YOU STAYED
AND WATCHED?
- I DID.
PRO BENDING TURNED OUT
TO BE THE PERFECT
TEACHING TOOL FOR YOU.
- I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW
FOR AIRBENDING PRACTICE.
BRIGHT AND EARLY.
AND, BY THE WAY, I KIND OF
PERMANENTLY JOINED
THE FIRE FERRETS, AND
WE'RE PLAYING IN THE TOURNAMENT
IN A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
- [sighs]