- EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR...
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
- A CHANCE ENCOUNTER
TURNS KORRA
FROM PRO BENDING SPECTATOR
TO PRO BENDING STAR,
WITH HER NEW TEAMMATES,
MAKO AND BOLIN,
THE FIRE FERRETS
EARN A PLACE
IN THE CHAMPIONSHIP
TOURNAMENT.
BUT MEANWHILE,
AN ANTI-BENDING REVOLUTION BREWS
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
WHO ARE THE EQUALISTS,
AND WHAT NEFARIOUS PLAN
DOES THE MYSTERIOUS MAN
BEHIND THE MASK
HAVE IN STORE FOR OUR HERO?
[tranquil music]
♪ ♪
- WHAT'S THE BIG IDEA
WITH MAKING ME TRAIN
THIS EARLY IN THE MORNING?
THE MORNING IS EVIL.
- WE'RE THE ROOKIES,
SO WE GET THE WORST
TIME SLOT IN THE GYM.
- AND YOU'RE
THE ROOKIEST OF US ALL.
WE GOTTA GET YOU
UP TO SPEED
IF WE WANT TO SURVIVE
IN THE TOURNAMENT.
DEAL WITH IT.
- YOU DEAL WITH IT.
- OOH!
UGH.
- THERE ARE MY LITTLE
HARDWORKING STREET URCHINS.
[Pabu squeaks]
IT'S AN HONOR TO FINALLY
MEET YOU, AVATAR.
- AND YOU ARE?
- BUTAKHA.
I RUN THIS WHOLE
PRO BENDING SHEBANG.
HERE'S YOUR WINNINGS
FROM THE LAST MATCH.
AH, AH, AH.
BUT NOT SO FAST.
FIRST, YOU OWE ME
FOR THE AVATAR'S NEW GEAR,
GYM AND EQUIPMENT RENTALS
FOR LAST MONTH,
RENT ON YOUR APARTMENT,
AND A PERSONAL LOAN
FOR GROCERIES.
- WHAT?
I'M A GROWING BOY.
- OH, AND ONE MORE SMALL ITEM
OF BUSINESS.
THE FIRE FERRETS NEED
TO ANTE UP 30,000 YUANS
FOR THE CHAMPIONSHIP POT.
- 30,000 YUANS?
- SORRY, KIDS.
YOU'VE GOT TILL
THE END OF THE WEEK
TO COME UP WITH THE DOUGH,
OR ELSE YOU'RE OUT
OF THE TOURNAMENT.
- YOU WOULDN'T
HAPPEN TO HAVE
A SECRET AVATAR BANK ACCOUNT
OVERFLOWING WITH GOLD,
WOULD YOU?
- I GOT NOTHING.
I'VE NEVER REALLY
NEEDED MONEY.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD
PEOPLE TAKING CARE OF ME.
- THEN I WOULDN'T SAY
YOU HAD NOTHING.
- SORRY, I DIDN'T MEAN--
- NO, IT'S ALL RIGHT,
IT'S JUST...
EVER SINCE
WE LOST OUR PARENTS,
WE'VE BEEN ON OUR OWN.
- I'M SO SORRY.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
- SO ANYWAY...
HOW ARE WE GOING
TO COME UP WITH THE MONEY?
- OOH, OOH,
I GOT IT, I GOT IT.
I'VE BEEN TRAINING PABU
TO DO CIRCUS TRICKS.
NOW PEOPLE WOULD PAY
GOOD MONEY TO SEE THAT.
- COME ON, BOLIN.
WE NEED SERIOUS IDEAS.
- I WAS SERIOUS.
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I'LL FIGURE SOMETHING OUT.
I ALWAYS DO.
- COME ONE, COME ALL.
SEE PABU,
THE FANTASTIC FIRE FERRET,
AS HE CROSSES
THE LADDER OF PERIL...
[gasps]
UPSIDE DOWN.
[Pabu licks noisily]
PSST, PSST.
[Pabu chitters]
BIG FINISH, BUDDY.
STICK THE LANDING.
TA-DAH!
THANK YOU,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
YOU ARE TOO KIND.
SERIOUSLY, TOO KIND.
YOU CAN COME BACK HERE
AND PUT MONEY RIGHT IN THIS--
[coin rattles] OKAY.
THAT'S FINE. THAT'S FINE.
1 YUAN DOWN, 29,999 TO GO.
[engine revs and stops]
- HEY, BOLIN.
IS THAT YOU?
- OH, HEY, THERE,
"SHADY" SHIN.
- HEARD YOU'RE A BIG TIME
PRO BENDING PLAYER NOW.
NOT BAD.
- UH, THANKS.
- SO LISTEN,
I GOT AN OFFER FOR YOU.
"LIGHTNING BOLT" ZOLT IS LOOKING
TO HIRE SOME EXTRA MUSCLE.
- UH, I DON'T KNOW, SHIN.
MAKO TOLD ME TO STAY AWAY
FROM THE TRIPLE THREATS.
- [scoffs] YOUR BROTHER
AIN'T THE BOSS OF YOU.
IT'S JUST
A LITTLE SECURITY WORK.
NOTHING CROOKED.
- [excitedly gasps]
- YOU GAME?
[energy crackling]
[whistle blows]
- [sighs]
BO,
I'M BACK.
PICKED UP
YOUR FAVORITE DUMPLINGS.
[sighs]
HEY, I FOUND SOME WORK
DOWN AT THE POWER PLANT.
IT'S SOME DECENT MONEY.
BOLIN?
YOU HERE, BRO?
[zither music]
♪ ♪
HUH, I BET THE LITTLE LOVE BIRD
IS MAKING A HOUSE CALL.
[wind rustling]
- GOOD,
LIGHT ON YOUR FEET.
OOH, HE'S CUTE.
KORRA, IS THAT
THE HANDSOME FIREBENDER BOY
THAT DRIVES YOU CRAZY?
- DOES HE DRIVE YOU CRAZY
IN A BAD WAY,
OR DOES HE DRIVE YOU CRAZY,
LIKE YOU LIKE HIM?
[ground thuds]
- [clears throat]
[girls giggling]
OH, HEY, MAKO.
- YOU SEEN BOLIN?
- NICE TO SEE YOU TOO.
AND NO, I HAVEN'T
SEEN HIM SINCE PRACTICE.
THINK SOMETHING'S WRONG?
- I DON'T KNOW.
BOLIN HAS A KNACK FOR GETTING
INTO STUPID SITUATIONS.
[sighs]
SEE YOU LATER.
- WAIT.
I COULD, UH,
HELP YOU LOOK FOR HIM.
- NAH, I GOT IT.
- HEY, COOL GUY,
LET ME HELP YOU.
WE CAN TAKE NAGA.
- WHO'S NAGA?
- MY BEST FRIEND,
AND A GREAT TRACKER.
- YOUR BEST FRIEND
IS A...POLAR BEAR DOG.
SOMEHOW THAT
MAKES PERFECT SENSE.
- I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A COMPLIMENT, CITY BOY.
- WELL,
THIS IS HIS USUAL HANGOUT.
[children laughing]
- YAY.
- WHOA.
- YOU GUYS SEE MY BROTHER
AROUND HERE TODAY?
- PERHAPS.
MY MEMORY'S
A LITTLE...FOGGY.
MAYBE YOU CAN HELP
CLEAR IT UP.
- YOU'RE GOOD, SKOOCHY.
A REAL PRO.
- YEAH, I'VE SEEN HIM.
- WHEN?
- ABOUT NOON.
- WHAT WAS HE DOING?
- HE WAS PERFORMING
SOME KIND OF MONKEY-RAT CIRCUS.
AND THEN...
- AND THEN WHAT?
WHY'D HE LEAVE?
- "SHADY" SHIN SHOWED UP
AND FLASHED SOME SERIOUS CASH.
BO TOOK OFF WITH HIM
IN HIS HOT ROD.
THE TRIPLE THREATS,
THE RED MONSOONS,
THE AGNI KAIS...
ALL THE TRIADS ARE MUSCLING UP
FOR SOMETHING REAL BIG.
NOW THAT'S ALL
YOU'RE GETTING OUT OF ME.
- WHAT'S HE TALKING ABOUT?
- SOUNDS LIKE
THERE'S A TURF WAR BREWING,
AND BOLIN'S ABOUT TO GET CAUGHT
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF IT.
- SO WHERE ARE WE HEADED?
- THE TRIPLE THREAT TRIAD'S
HEADQUARTERS.
HOPEFULLY BOLIN'S THERE
AND NOTHING'S GONE DOWN YET.
- TRIPLE THREAT TRIAD?
I BEAT UP SOME OF THOSE YAHOOS
WHEN I GOT INTO TOWN.
WHY WOULD BOLIN
GET TANGLED UP WITH--
[Naga growls]
WHOA, NAGA.
[Pabu squeaks]
- THAT'S PABU.
[Naga barks]
- NO, NAGA.
PABU'S A FRIEND,
NOT A SNACK.
[Pabu chitters]
- WE GOTTA HURRY.
SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT.
THERE ARE USUALLY THUGS
POSTED OUT FRONT.
WE BETTER BE CAUTIOUS.
[loud crash]
BOLIN?
YOU IN HERE?
[engine revs]
[motorcycles rev]
- [muffled grunting]
- BOLIN!
[wheels screech]
[both coughing]
- NAGA, COME!
[Naga panting]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[pavement rumbling]
[motorcycle revs]
[ropes whirl]
- [gasps]
- [groans]
- OHH.
- [grunting]
[groaning]
- [groaning]
- OOH...
- UH...
[Naga growling]
[ropes swishing]
[growling]
[roaring]
[Pabu squeaking]
[engine reving]
[grunts]
UGH! I CAN'T BEND.
I CAN'T BEND!
- CALM DOWN,
IT'LL WEAR OFF.
THOSE GUYS
WERE CHI-BLOCKERS.
THEY'RE AMON'S HENCHMEN.
- AMON? THAT ANTI-BENDING
GUY WITH THE MASK?
- YEAH, HE'S THE LEADER
OF THE EQUALISTS.
- WHAT DO THEY WANT
WITH THE TRIPLE THREATS?
- WHATEVER IT IS,
IT CAN'T BE GOOD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE BOLIN
GOT HIMSELF INTO THIS MESS.
- MAKO, WE ARE GOING
TO SAVE YOUR BROTHER.
I PROMISE YOU THAT.
[melancholy music]
♪ ♪
[Naga panting]
WE'VE BEEN OUT ALL NIGHT.
NO SIGN OF HIM.
- WE'VE GOTTA KEEP LOOKING.
BUT WHERE?
- [gasps]
I HAVE AN IDEA.
THE FIRST DAY
I GOT INTO TOWN,
I RAN INTO AN EQUALIST
PROTESTER OVER THERE.
- AND YOU THINK THEY'LL KNOW
WHERE BOLIN IS?
- IT'S OUR
ONLY LEAD RIGHT NOW.
[dispirited music]
♪ ♪
SO, WHY IS BOLIN
RUNNING AROUND
WITH THE TRIPLE THREAT TRIAD,
ANYWAY?
- WELL, WE--WE USED TO DO SOME
WORK FOR THEM BACK IN THE DAY.
- WHAT?
ARE YOU
SOME KIND OF CRIMINAL?
- NO.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I JUST RAN NUMBERS
FOR THEM AND STUFF.
WE WERE ORPHANS
OUT ON THE STREET.
I DID WHAT I HAD
TO DO TO SURVIVE
AND PROTECT MY LITTLE BROTHER.
- I'M SORRY.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
REALLY HARD.
CAN I ASK WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR PARENTS?
- [sighs]
THEY WERE MUGGED
BY A FIREBENDER.
HE CUT THEM DOWN
RIGHT IN FRONT OF ME.
I WAS EIGHT.
- MAKO...
- BOLIN'S THE ONLY FAMILY
I HAVE LEFT.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENED TO HIM...
- [over loudspeaker]
EQUALITY NOW!
WE WANT EQUALITY NOW!
- HMM...
AHH!
[stammers
and clears throat]
- NON-BENDERS
OF REPUBLIC CITY.
- THAT'S THE GUY.
- AMON CALLS YOU TO ACTION.
TAKE BACK YOUR CITY.
IT'S TIME FOR THE--
[gasps]
IT'S YOU AGAIN.
YOU CANNOT SILENCE ME,
AVATAR.
[yelps]
- SHUT YOUR YAPPER
AND LISTEN UP.
MY FRIEND GOT KIDNAPPED
BY SOME CHI-BLOCKERS.
WHERE'D THEY TAKE HIM?
- I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
- OH, I THINK YOU DO.
[ground thuds]
- WHOA--
- [groans]
- "WITNESS THE REVELATION
TONIGHT, 9:00."
WHAT'S THIS REVELATION?
- NOTHING THAT CONCERNS
THE LIKES OF YOU TWO.
[shrieks]
- YOU BETTER BELIEVE
IT CONCERNS US.
SPILL IT.
- NO ONE KNOWS
WHAT THE REVELATION IS.
AND I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR FRIEND.
BUT IF HE'S A BENDER,
THEN MY BET IS
HE'S GETTING
WHAT'S COMING TO HIM.
- WHERE'S IT HAPPENING?
[whistle blowing]
- HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON
OVER THERE?
- THE AVATAR'S OPPRESSING US.
HELP!
- LET'S SCRAM.
WHY DIDN'T THE EQUALISTS
PUT A LOCATION ON THESE?
- PROBABLY BECAUSE THEY DON'T
WANT JUST ANYONE
WALTZING INTO
THEIR BIG REVELATION.
WHATEVER THAT IS.
I BET THE INFORMATION
IS HIDDEN ON HERE SOMEHOW.
LOOK AT THE BACKS.
THERE'S FOUR DIFFERENT IMAGES.
- SO IT'S A PUZZLE?
- YEAH...OF A MAP.
BINGO.
THAT MUST BE
WHERE IT'S GOING DOWN.
- THIS IS THE PLACE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WE'LL ATTRACT
LESS ATTENTION THIS WAY.
- THIS IS PRIVATE EVENT.
NO ONE GETS IN
WITHOUT AN INVITATION.
- UH, INVITATION?
- YOU MEAN THIS?
- THE REVELATION IS UPON US,
MY BROTHER AND SISTER.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- I KNEW A LOT OF PEOPLE
HATED BENDERS,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN
SO MANY IN ONE PLACE.
KEEP YOUR EYES OUT FOR BOLIN.
- PLEASE WELCOME YOUR HERO,
YOUR SAVIOR,
AMON!
[cheers and applause]
[sinister music]
♪ ♪
- MY QUEST FOR EQUALITY
BEGAN MANY YEARS AGO.
WHEN I WAS A BOY,
MY FAMILY AND I LIVED
ON A SMALL FARM.
WE WEREN'T RICH,
AND NONE OF US WERE BENDERS.
THIS MADE US VERY EASY TARGETS
FOR THE FIREBENDER
WHO EXTORTED MY FATHER.
ONE DAY,
MY FATHER CONFRONTED THIS MAN,
BUT WHEN HE DID...
THAT FIREBENDER
TOOK MY FAMILY FROM ME...
THEN HE TOOK MY FACE.
[crowd gasps]
I'VE BEEN FORCED TO HIDE BEHIND
A MASK EVER SINCE.
AS YOU KNOW,
THE AVATAR HAS RECENTLY
ARRIVED IN REPUBLIC CITY.
[crowd boos loudly]
AND IF SHE WERE HERE,
SHE WOULD TELL YOU
THAT BENDING BRINGS BALANCE
TO THE WORLD,
BUT SHE IS WRONG.
THE ONLY THING BENDING
HAS BROUGHT TO THE WORLD
IS SUFFERING.
IT HAS BEEN THE CAUSE
OF EVERY WAR IN EVERY ERA,
BUT THAT IS ABOUT TO CHANGE.
I KNOW YOU HAVE BEEN WONDERING,
"WHAT IS THE REVELATION?"
YOU ARE ABOUT
TO GET YOUR ANSWER.
SINCE THE BEGINNING OF TIME,
THE SPIRITS HAVE ACTED
AS GUARDIANS OF OUR WORLD,
AND THEY HAVE SPOKEN TO ME.
THEY SAY THE AVATAR
HAS FAILED HUMANITY,
THAT IS WHY THE SPIRITS
HAVE CHOSEN ME
TO USHER IN
A NEW ERA OF BALANCE.
THEY HAVE GRANTED ME A POWER
THAT WILL MAKE EQUALITY
A REALITY--
THE POWER TO TAKE
A PERSON'S BENDING AWAY...
PERMANENTLY.
- THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE'S NO WAY.
- THIS GUY IS INSANE.
- NOW FOR A DEMONSTRATION.
PLEASE WELCOME
"LIGHTNING BOLT" ZOLT,
LEADER OF
THE TRIPLE THREAT TRIAD,
AND ONE OF
THE MOST NOTORIOUS CRIMINALS
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
[crowd boos]
- AH, BOO YOURSELF.
- THERE'S BOLIN.
- WAIT.
WE CAN'T FIGHT THEM ALL.
WE NEED TO BE SMART
ABOUT THIS.
- THEN COME UP WITH
A GAME PLAN,
TEAM CAPTAIN.
- ZOLT HAS AMASSED
A FORTUNE
BY EXTORTING AND ABUSING
NON-BENDERS,
BUT HIS REIGN OF TERROR
IS ABOUT TO COME TO AN END.
NOW, IN THE INTEREST
OF FAIRNESS,
I WILL GIVE ZOLT THE CHANCE
TO FIGHT TO KEEP HIS BENDING.
- YOU'RE GOING
TO REGRET DOING THAT, PAL.
[fire ball explodes]
[electricity crackles]
[loud explosions]
[gasps]
[groans]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[groans]
[grunts]
[audience murmurs in awe]
WHAT--WHAT
DID YOU DO TO ME?
- YOUR FIREBENDING IS GONE...
FOREVER.
[audience gasps]
THE ERA OF BENDING IS OVER.
A NEW ERA OF EQUALITY
HAS BEGUN!
[cheers and applause]
- HMM?
HEY.
OH...
HUH...NO,
UGH!
- ANY IDEAS YET?
- I THINK SO.
SEE THOSE MACHINES?
THEY'RE POWERED
BY WATER AND STEAM.
IF YOU CREATE SOME COVER,
I CAN GRAB BOLIN
WITHOUT ANYONE SEEING.
THEN WE DUCK OUT OF HERE.
- WORKS FOR ME.
MAKO, GOOD LUCK.
- YOU TOO.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[wheel creaks]
- [grunts]
NO, IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
- HEY, YOU.
♪ ♪
- [groaning]
[cheers and applause]
- [gasps]
- IS THERE A PROBLEM,
MY BROTHER?
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
BACK HERE?
- UH, LOOKING FOR
THE BATHROOM?
[clicks tool]
- [grunting]
[pipe clangs]
- COME ON.
[pipes clang]
- [gasps]
WHOA--WHOA--
[groans]
- THANKS.
THIS SHOULD BE ENOUGH.
- OOH.
[gasps]
[whimpering]
[groans]
[audience cheers]
UH, HELLO.
AMON, SIR.
I THINK THERE'S BEEN
A BIG MISUNDERSTANDING.
[air whooshing]
[loud explosion]
[audience screaming]
- [gasps]
UGH--
- [screams]
- BOLIN, YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YES, MAKO!
I LOVE YOU.
[door slams open]
[electricity zapping]
[both screaming]
[groaning]
[electricity crackles]
- [groaning]
- UGH!
YAH!
[groaning]
[screaming]
- [grunts]
[electricity crackles]
[groans]
[screaming]
- YOU BENDERS NEED
TO UNDERSTAND
THERE'S NO PLACE IN THE WORLD
FOR YOU ANYMORE.
[pavement loudly cracks]
[groans]
[panting]
- I WOULDN'T COUNT US OUT
JUST YET.
- [groans]
- [whistles]
NAGA!
[Naga barks]
- [screaming]
AH! OH! YAH!
GUYS, STOP!
I WANT...TO BE...
ON...YOUR BACK.
- THE AVATAR--THAT'S HER.
- LET HER GO.
SHE'S THE PERFECT MESSENGER
TO TELL THE CITY
OF MY POWER.
- THANK GOODNESS.
I WAS JUST ABOUT
TO SEND OUT A SEARCH PARTY.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- MM-MM.
- KORRA, WHAT HAPPENED?
DID YOU FIND YOUR FRIEND?
- YES, BUT...
I WAS AT AN EQUALIST RALLY.
I SAW AMON.
- WHAT?
- HE CAN TAKE
PEOPLE'S BENDING AWAY FOR GOOD.
- THAT'S--THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
ONLY THE AVATAR HAS EVER
POSSESSED THAT ABILITY.
- BUT I SAW HIM DO IT.
- I BELIEVE YOU.
I DON'T KNOW HOW AMON HAS
ACHIEVED THIS POWER...
BUT THIS MEANS THE REVOLUTION
IS MORE DANGEROUS THAN EVER.
NO BENDER IS SAFE.
[somber music]