Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring baIance to the world.
Benders, be on alert!
After coming face to face with Amon,
Ieader of the EquaIists,
Avatar Korra discovers a terrifying truth!
This masked madman has the abiIity
to take away a person's bending,
permanentIy!
Benders of Republic City
are counting on their young Avatar.
But is she prepared to face
such a frightening foe?
After l take your bending away,
you will be nothing!
lt's all right, Naga.
l just had a bad dream.
There is a madman running around
our beloved city,
threatening to tear it apart.
We need to create a task force
whose sole mission is to find Amon
and bring him to justice.
Absolutely not.
A move that aggressive would only
further divide benders and non-benders.
Tarrlok, l'm inclined to agree
with your proposal.
But who would even head up
such a task force?
lt would be my honor
and privilege to accept such a duty.
This is just another one of your ploys
to gain more power, isn't it?
All l'm trying to do is help. Think back.
Forty-two years ago,
Republic City was threatened
by another dangerous man,
Yakone.
Your father wasn't afraid
to deal with him head on.
This is a completely different situation.
And how dare you compare
yourself to Avatar Aang!
Amon is not going to stop
with the bending Triads.
Eventually he will come
for all us benders,
our friends, our families.
Vote for this task force
and l will stop Amon before it's too late.
All in favor?
Good evening, my fellow Equalists.
This is your Ieader, Amon.
As you have heard,
the Republic Council has voted
to make me pubIic enemy number one,
proving once again that
the bending oppressors of this city
wiII stop at nothing
to quash our revoIution.
But we cannot be stopped,
our numbers grow stronger by the day.
You no Ionger have to Iive in fear.
The time has come
for benders to experience fear.
No! l'm so sorry! l didn't see you!
How could you not see me?
l mean, l was...
l was, l... l... That was...
Are you okay? Did l hurt you?
l am such an idiot.
Don't worry, l'm fine.
My brother hits me harder than that
every day in practice.
Wait, l recognize you.
You're Mako, right?
You play for the Fire Ferrets!
Yeah, that's me.
l am so embarrassed!
My name's Asami.
Let me make this up to you somehow.
How about l treat you to dinner?
Tomorrow night, 8:00, Kwong's Cuisine.
Kwong's?
l don't have any clothes nice enough
for a place that classy.
l'll take care of that.
All you need to do is show up.
So, it's a date?
Yeah, l guess so.
l'll see you tomorrow night.
We are grateful for this delicious food,
for happiness, for compassion and...
l'm not interrupting, am l?
This is my home, Tarrlok.
We're about to eat dinner.
Good, because
l am absolutely famished.
Airbenders never turn away
a hungry guest, am l right?
l suppose.
You must be the famous Avatar Korra.
lt is truly an honor.
l am Councilman Tarrlok,
representative
from the Northern Water Tribe.
Nice to meet you.
Why do you have three ponytails?
And how come you smell
like a lady? You're weird.
Well, aren't you
precocious?
So, l've been reading all
about your adventures in the papers.
lnfiltrating Amon's rally,
now, that took some real initiative.
Thanks. l think you're the first
authority figure in this city
who's happy l'm here.
Republic City is much better off
now that you've arrived.
Enough with the flattery, Tarrlok.
What do you want from Korra?
Patience, Tenzin, l'm getting to that.
As you may have heard,
l am assembling a task force
that will strike at the heart
of the revolution,
and l want you to join me.
-Really?
-What?
l need someone who will help me
attack Amon directly,
someone who is fearless
in the face of danger,
and that someone is you.
Join your task force?
l can't.
l must admit, l'm rather surprised.
l thought you'd jump at the chance
to help me lead the charge
against Amon.
Me, too.
l came to Republic City to finish
my Avatar training with Tenzin.
Right now, l just need to focus on that.
Which is why this opportunity is perfect.
You would get on-the-job experience
while performing
your Avatar duty for the city.
Korra gave you her answer.
lt's time for you to go.
Very well.
But l'm not giving up on you just yet.
You'll be hearing from me soon.
lt has been a pleasure, Avatar Korra.
Bye-bye, ponytail man!
Welcome to Kwong's Cuisine,
Master Mako.
"Master"?
The scarf stays.
As you wish, sir. This way, please.
l am such a big Pro-bending fan.
l caught all of your matches this season.
All of them?
Honestly, there were a few
l wish you hadn't seen.
Don't be ridiculous. You're amazing!
l can't wait to see
you play in the tournament.
Yeah, well... Maybe next year.
What do you mean? You made it in.
lt just isn't in the cards for us right now.
Tell me, what's the problem?
We don't have the cash to ante up
for the championship pot.
So, it looks like we're out of the running.
That's not fair.
Pardon me, Miss Sato.
Your main course.
Miss Sato?
You wouldn't happen to be related
to Hiroshi Sato,
creator of the Sato-mobile?
-Yeah, he's my dad.
-Get out of town!
l'm serious. You want to meet him?
Meet the most successful captain
of industry in all of Republic City?
Yeah, l'll take you up on that.
Hello, fellow teammate!
Hey, Bolin.
Missed you at practice this week.
Yeah, sorry about that.
lt's all right. We're probably out
of the tournament anyway,
unless some money miraculously
drops out of the sky by tomorrow.
Anyway, reason l came by
was to give you this.
Thanks. What's this for?
l can't remember now.
Yeah, now l remember.
You saved me from Amon.
That? lt was no big deal.
No big deal? Are you serious?
l was totally freaking out
when he was coming at me
with his creepy mask, all,
"l will take away your bending forever!"
l mean, that is scary stuff.
l still can't sleep well.
Delivery for Avatar Korra!
Tarrlok sends his compliments
and urges you to reconsider his offer.
Tell him l haven't changed my mind.
Who's this Tarrlok guy?
ls he bothering you?
'Cause l could have a word with him.
No, it's not like that.
He's just some old guy
who works with Tenzin on the Council.
Good, good. That sounds better.
l like that better.
What do you think
of my little operation here?
lt's very impressive, Mr. Sato.
Please, call me Hiroshi.
-So, l understand you're dirt poor.
-Well...
Young man,
it is nothing to be ashamed of.
l, too, came from humble beginnings.
Why, when l was your age,
l was a mere shoe shiner.
And all l had to my name was an idea...
The Sato-mobile.
Now, l was fortunate enough
to meet someone
who believed in me and my work ethic.
He gave me the money l needed
to get my idea off the ground.
And l built
the entire Future lndustries empire
from that one, selfless loan.
Dad, stop bragging.
Just tell Mako the good news.
What good news?
Well, my daughter passionately told me
all about your hard-earned success
in the Pro-bending Arena,
and about your team's current
financial stumbling block.
Now l'd hate to see you lose
your chance
at winning the championship,
just because you're short a few yuans.
That's why l'm going to sponsor
the Fire Ferrets in the tournament!
-Are you serious?
-He's serious!
My dad's going to cover your ante
for the championship pot.
That... That is good news!
There's just one catch,
you all have to wear the Future
lndustries logo on your uniforms.
l'll tattoo it on my chest if you want, sir!
Thank you both so much!
l promise the Fire Ferrets will make
the most of this opportunity!
Out of the way, Daddy!
We're driving here!
l see Tarrlok's gifts are getting more
and more extravagant.
Yeah, that guy doesn't know
how to take no for an answer.
Korra, are you doing all right?
Yeah, l'm fine.
Why don't you take a break?
l'm glad you turned down Tarrlok,
but l just wanted to make sure
your decision was for the right reason.
l'm just really focused
on my airbending right now is all.
Right, that's what you said.
You know, it's okay to be scared.
The whole city is frightened
by what's been going on.
The important thing
is to talk about our fears.
Because if we don't,
they can throw us out of balance.
l'm always here for you,
if you want to talk.
Avatar Korra, l have something for you.
lt doesn't matter
how many gifts Tarrlok sends,
l'm not joining his task force.
lt's not a gift, it's an invitation!
To what?
Tarrlok is throwing a gala in your honor.
All of Republic City's movers
and shakers will be there.
The Councilman humbly requests
your attendance.
l can't believe this is all for me.
l'm not sure what Tarrlok's plotting,
but keep your guard up.
lt's not like him to throw a party
just for the fun of it.
So glad you could make it, Avatar Korra.
lf you'll excuse us,
the city awaits its hero.
Meelo, no! That is not a toilet! Oh, dear.
Korra, it is my pleasure to introduce
Republic City's most famous
industrialist, Hiroshi Sato.
Nice to meet you.
We're all expecting great things
from you.
Right. Greatness.
Hey, Korra.
This is my daughter, Asami.
lt's lovely to meet you.
Mako told me so much about you.
Really? Because he hasn't mentioned
you at all.
How did you two meet?
Asami crashed into him on her moped.
What? Are you okay?
l'm fine. More than fine!
Mr. Sato agreed to sponsor our team.
We're back in the tournament!
lsn't that great?
Yeah, terrific.
Chief Beifong, l believe you and
Avatar Korra have already met.
Just because the city's throwing you
this big to-do,
don't think you're something special.
You've done absolutely nothing
to deserve this.
lf you'd be so kind,
they just have a couple questions.
But...
Avatar Korra, you witnessed Amon
take away people's bending firsthand.
How serious a threat does he pose
to the innocent citizens
of Republic City?
l think... He presents a real problem.
Then why have you refused to join
Tarrlok's task force?
As the Avatar,
shouldn't you be going after Amon?
Well... l...
Why are you backing away
from this fight?
What? No. l've never backed away
from anything in my life.
You promised to serve this city.
Aren't you going back
on that promise now?
Do you think Pro-bending is more
important than fighting the revolution?
How do you think
Avatar Aang would have handled this?
Are you afraid ofAmon?
l'm not afraid of anybody!
lf the city needs me, then...
l'll join Tarrlok's task force
and help fight Amon.
There's your headline, folks!
My fellow task force deputies,
tonight we will execute a raid
on an underground Chi-blocker
training camp
located in the Dragon Flats borough.
According to my sources,
there is a cellar underneath
this bookstore
where Equalists train Chi-blocking
in secret.
l'm going after those two!
Nice timing. Thanks, Tarrlok.
We make a good team, Avatar.
Yeah, we do!
No Korra for practice again?
Doesn't look like it.
Avatar Korra has braveIy answered
the call to action.
With the two of us Ieading the charge,
Republic City has nothing to fear
from Amon and the EquaIists!
Question for the Avatar.
Amon remains at large.
Why have you failed to locate him?
You wanna know why?
Because Amon is hiding in the shadows
like a coward!
Amon, I chaIIenge you to a dueI!
No task force, no Chi-blockers.
Just the two of us, tonight at midnight
on Avatar Aang MemoriaI IsIand.
Let's cut to the chase
and settIe this thing,
if you're man enough to face me!
l know it sounds weird to say this,
but l'm really glad l hit you
with my moped.
Me, too.
l forgot to ask,
why didn't you accept the new silk scarf
l bought for you last week?
-You didn't like it?
-No, it was really nice. But...
This scarf was my father's,
and it's all l have left of him.
l just feel like... Like it keeps me safe.
l'm so sorry. l lost my mother
when l was very young.
l feel so safe with you.
Korra, this is madness.
Don't try to stop me,
and don't follow me!
l have to face Amon alone.
This is all your doing!
l tried to talk her out of it, too,
but she's made up her mind.
We'll be watching the island closely.
lf anything goes wrong,
l have a fleet of police airships
ready to swoop down.
Guess you're a no-show, Amon.
Who's scared now?
l received your invitation, young Avatar.
Our showdown, while inevitable,
is premature.
Although it would be the simplest thing
for me to take away
your bending right now,
l won't.
You'd only become a martyr.
Benders of every nation would rally
behind your untimely demise.
But l assure you, l have a plan,
and l'm saving you for last.
Then you'll get your duel,
and l will destroy you.
-Aang...
-Korra!
Korra, are you all right?
What happened? Was Amon here?
Yeah. He ambushed me.
Did he...
Did he take your bending away?
No. l'm okay.
Thank goodness.
l was so terrified! l felt so helpless!
lt's all right, the nightmare is over.
You... You were right.
l've been scared this whole time.
l've never felt like this before and...
Tenzin, l don't know what to do!
Admitting your fears
is the first and most difficult step
in overcoming them.