- EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR...
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
- LOVE IS IN THE AIR.
SINCE AVATAR KORRA
HAS ARRIVED IN REPUBLIC CITY,
SHE'S ONLY HAD EYES
FOR ONE FELLA--MAKO.
THE FEELING SEEMED MUTUAL UNTIL
A FATEFUL ACCIDENT INTERVENED!
NOW, MAKO'S AFFECTIONS
HAVE FALLEN
RIGHT INTO THE ARMS
OF THE BEAUTIFUL ASAMI.
WILL LOVE PROVE TO BE KORRA'S
MOST FORMIDABLE FOE YET?
[lively music]
♪ ♪
- [grunting]
- OOH!
[thud]
[laughter]
- IT'S BEEN GREAT HAVING YOU
AT SO MANY BACK-TO-BACK
PRACTICES, KORRA.
- FEELS GOOD TO BE BACK,
ALTHOUGH TARRLOK ISN'T TOO HAPPY
ABOUT MY LEAVE OF ABSENCE.
- HEY, YOU JOINED
THE FIRE FERRETS
BEFORE YOU JOINED
HIS TASK FORCE.
- OKAY, COME ON.
TEAM HUDDLE TIME.
AHEM.
IT'S OUR FIRST MATCH
OF THE TOURNAMENT TONIGHT.
I KNOW THE THREE OF US HAVEN'T
BEEN A TEAM FOR VERY LONG,
BUT EVEN SO,
THE FIRE FERRETS
HAVE NEVER BEEN THIS GOOD.
ARE WE READY?
- WE'RE READY!
- NOT QUITE.
YOU'LL NEED THESE.
- HEY, ASAMI.
- GOOD MORNING, SWEETIE.
- THESE NEW UNIFORMS
LOOK GREAT.
- YOU LOOK GREAT, CHAMP.
[softly laughing]
- [gagging]
- WELL, TEAMMATES,
I'LL SEE YOU BEFORE
THE MATCH TONIGHT.
ASAMI AND I HAVE
A LUNCH DATE.
- OKAY, WE'LL CHECK
YOU GUYS LATER.
YOU KNOW, WE'LL SEE YOU
WHEN WE SEE YOU.
SO, KORRA...
THERE THEY GO,
HERE WE ARE.
ALL ALONE IN THE GYM.
JUST YOU AND ME,
TWO ALONE PEOPLE.
TOGETHER.
ALONE.
- UH...I GOT TO HEAD BACK
TO THE AIR TEMPLE
TO TRAIN WITH TENZIN.
SEE YA!
[Pabu chittering]
- WORK WITH ME HERE, PABU.
YOU WANT TO LOOK SPIC-AND-SPAN
IN YOUR NEW UNIFORM,
DON'T YOU?
[Pabu chittering]
[splash]
SO...
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF KORRA
IN A GIRLFRIEND SORT OF WAY?
- SHE'S GREAT,
BUT I THINK
IT MAKES MORE SENSE
FOR ME TO GO FOR ASAMI.
- I WAS TALKING ABOUT
A GIRLFRIEND FOR ME.
LEAVE SOME LADIES
FOR THE REST OF US.
- I KNOW, THAT'S WHAT
I THOUGHT YOU MEANT.
- WELL?
- I DON'T KNOW, BO.
IT DOESN'T SEEM
LIKE A GOOD IDEA
FOR YOU TO DATE KORRA.
- YOU JUST SAID SHE WAS GREAT
TWO SECONDS AGO.
- YEAH, KORRA'S A GREAT ATHLETE
AND AVATAR AND STUFF,
BUT I DON'T KNOW IF SHE'S
REALLY GIRLFRIEND MATERIAL.
SHE'S MORE LIKE A PAL.
- BRO, YOU'RE NUTS.
KORRA AND I ARE PERFECT
FOR EACH OTHER.
SHE'S STRONG, I'M STRONG.
SHE'S FUN, I'M FUN.
SHE'S BEAUTIFUL,
I'M GORGEOUS.
OKAY, I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU THINK,
I'M GONNA ASK KORRA OUT.
- LOOK, IT JUST ISN'T SMART
TO DATE A TEAMMATE,
ESPECIALLY DURING
THE TOURNAMENT.
KEEP YOUR HEAD
OUT OF THE CLOUDS
AND YOUR PRIORITIES STRAIGHT,
OKAY?
- YEAH, YEAH,
I KNOW.
[sighs]
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT, PABU.
TALKING ABOUT REAL LOVE.
[Pabu chittering]
- SO, HOW'S IT GOING WITH
THE TALL, DREAMY FIREBENDER BOY?
YOU'VE BEEN SPENDING
A LOT OF TIME TOGETHER LATELY.
- OOH, YEAH.
TELL US ALL ABOUT
THE MAGICAL ROMANCE!
- WHAT?
[laughs]
LISTEN TO YOU TWO!
I'M--I'M NOT INTERESTED IN MAKO
OR ANY ROMANTIC STUFF.
[clears throat]
BESIDES,
HE'S ALL INTO THAT
PRISSY, BEAUTIFUL, ELEGANT
RICH GIRL.
BUT LET'S JUST PRETEND
FOR A SECOND
I AM INTERESTED IN HIM--
WHAT WOULD I DO?
- OOH, I JUST READ
A HISTORICAL SAGA
WHERE THE HEROINE FELL IN LOVE
WITH THE ENEMY GENERAL'S SON
WHO WAS SUPPOSED
TO MARRY THE PRINCESS.
YOU SHOULD DO WHAT SHE DID.
- TELL ME.
- SHE RODE HER DRAGON
INTO BATTLE
AND BURNED DOWN
THE ENTIRE COUNTRY.
THEN SHE JUMPED
INTO A VOLCANO.
IT WAS SO ROMANTIC.
- UH...
- NO, NO, NO!
THE BEST WAY
TO WIN A BOY'S HEART
IS TO BREW A LOVE POTION
OF RAINBOWS AND SUNSETS
THAT MAKES TRUE LOVERS
SPROUT WINGS
AND FLY TO A MAGICAL CASTLE
IN THE SKY
WHERE THEY GET MARRIED
AND EAT CLOUDS WITH SPOONS
AND USE STARS AS ICE CUBES
IN THEIR MOONLIGHT PUNCH
FOREVER AND EVER AND EVER.
- THE VOLCANO IS STARTING
TO MAKE MORE SENSE TO ME NOW.
- [laughs]
- OH, HEY, PEMA!
UH, HOW LONG WERE
YOU STANDING THERE?
- [laughs]
LONG ENOUGH.
BUT TRUST ME, I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE GOING THROUGH.
YEARS AGO, I WAS IN
THE EXACT SAME SITUATION.
WITH TENZIN.
- DADDY WAS IN LOVE
WITH SOMEONE ELSE BEFORE YOU?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- SO WHAT DID YOU DO?
- WELL, FOR THE LONGEST TIME
I DID NOTHING,
I WAS SO SHY AND SCARED
OF REJECTION.
BUT WATCHING MY SOUL MATE
SPEND HIS LIFE
WITH THE WRONG WOMAN
BECAME TOO PAINFUL.
SO I HUNG MY CHIN
OUT THERE,
AND I CONFESSED
MY LOVE TO TENZIN.
AND THE REST IS HISTORY.
all: WOW.
- FOLKS,
AFTER A YEAR OF WAITING,
THE PRO BENDING
CHAMPIONSHIP TOURNAMENT
IS FINALLY HERE.
TONIGHT IS THE FIRST
SET OF MATCHES
IN OUR SINGLE ELIMINATION,
16-TEAM BRACKET.
AND I GOTTA TELL YA,
THESE ARE
THE MOST TENACIOUS
AND TALENTED BENDING TRIOS
THIS ARENA HAS EVER SEEN.
- INTRODUCING OUR FIRST TEAM,
THE FUTURE INDUSTRIES
FIRE FERRETS!
- [cheering]
- AND THEIR OPPONENTS,
THE RED SANDS RABBAROOS.
[cheering]
[bell dings]
- WHAT AN EXPLOSIVE
OPENING VOLLEY.
BOTH TEAMS QUICKLY RECOVER
AND UNLEASH
A BARRAGE OF BENDING.
I AM ASTONISHED WITH THE LEVEL
OF IMPROVEMENT
DISPLAYED HERE
BY THE FIRE FERRETS.
NO WONDER THE AVATAR'S
BEEN ABSENT
FROM THE PAPERS LATELY.
SHE'S OBVIOUSLY HAD HER NOSE
TO THE GRINDSTONE
IN THE GYM.
THE FERRETS ADVANCE
INTO RABBAROO TERRITORY
AND ARE HOLDING
NOTHING BACK.
NICE SPRAWL
THERE BY MAKO.
BOLIN STRIKES.
ULA DODGES...
[buzzer rings]
AND ALL
THREE RABBAROOS ARE DOWN.
THE FIRE FERRETS
EASILY TAKE ROUND ONE.
[bell dings]
- ROUND TWO.
- THE RABBAROOS ARE LOOKING
FOR PAYBACK,
AND THEY GO STRAIGHT
AFTER BOLIN.
KORRA COMES TO HIS DEFENSE,
AND SHE WATER-WHACKS UMI
BACK INTO ZONE TWO.
THE FERRETS ARE ON FIRE TONIGHT,
AND THEY WIN ROUND TWO.
- ROUND THREE.
[bell dings]
- WITH THE RABAROOS
DOWN TWO ROUNDS,
THEY'LL NEED
A KNOCKOUT TO WIN.
AND WITH THE WAY
THE FIRE FERRETS ARE PLAYING,
I DON'T SEE THAT HAPPENING.
[buzzer rings]
- [panting]
[audience boos]
- THESE FERRETS
ARE WORKING TOGETHER
LIKE A WELL-OILED
BENDING MACHINE.
- HA! OOH,
YAH!
- [groans]
[buzzer rings]
- BOLIN BASHES ADI
INTO ZONE TWO,
AND THE FERRETS
GET THE GREEN LIGHT TO ADVANCE.
[cheering]
THE RABAROOS
ARE JUST FIGHTING
TO STAY ON THEIR FEET
AT THIS POINT.
- [groaning]
[buzzer rings]
DOWN GOES
ADI AND ULA AND UMI.
- ALL THREE ROUNDS
GO TO THE FUTURE INDUSTRIES
FIRE FERRETS
WHO WIN THEIR OPENING MATCH
OF THE TOURNAMENT.
- WHOO-HOO!
- YES!
- THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
- YEAH!
[cheering]
- THANK YOU.
- WOW.
WE WERE REALLY CONNECTING
OUT THERE IN THAT RING.
- YEAH, YOU KNOW,
I FEEL LIKE THE TWO OF US
HAVE BEEN CONNECTING REALLY WELL
OUT OF THE RING, TOO.
- UM, SURE.
- SO I WAS THINKING WE SHOULD
SPEND SOME TIME TOGETHER.
- WE'VE BEEN SPENDING
LOTS OF TIME TOGETHER.
- I MEAN
OUTSIDE OF THE GYM.
AND NOT WHILE SEARCHING
FOR KIDNAPPED FAMILY MEMBERS
OR FIGHTING CHI-BLOCKERS.
- I DON'T KNOW.
ASAMI AND I ARE--
- LOOK, I REALLY LIKE YOU,
AND I THINK WE WERE MEANT
FOR EACH OTHER.
- KORRA,
I'M REALLY SORRY, BUT...
I JUST DON'T FEEL
THE SAME WAY ABOUT YOU.
- FORGET I EVER SAID ANYTHING.
- CONGRATULATIONS, GUYS.
YOU WERE SO AMAZING OUT THERE.
MWAH.
[melancholy music]
♪ ♪
- SO, KORRA,
I WAS THINKING YOU AND ME,
WE COULD GO GET SOME DINNER
TOGETHER.
SORT OF A DATE SITUATION.
- OH, THAT'S REALLY SWEET,
BUT I DON'T THINK SO.
I DON'T FEEL VERY DATE-WORTHY.
- ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
YOU'RE THE SMARTEST,
FUNNIEST,
TOUGHEST, BUFF-EST,
TALENTED-EST,
INCREDIBLE-EST GIRL
IN THE WORLD.
- [giggles]
YOU REALLY FEEL
THAT WAY ABOUT ME?
- I FELT THAT WAY SINCE
THE MOMENT I SAW YOU.
TRUST ME, I KNOW WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE SO MUCH FUN TOGETHER.
- YOU KNOW WHAT,
I COULD USE SOME FUN.
OKAY, SURE.
- YES!
WHO'S THE LUCKIEST GUY
IN THE WORLD?
RIGHT HERE,
BOLIN.
- [slurping]
SO, HOW DO YOU LIKE IT?
- MMM, IT'S DELICIOUS,
AND TOTALLY AUTHENTIC.
MAN, I DIDN'T REALIZE HOW MUCH
I MISSED WATER TRIBE GRUB.
- THAT'S GREAT, BECAUSE
THIS IS MY FAVORITE JOINT.
SEE, YOU LOVE
WATER TRIBE FOOD,
I LOVE WATER TRIBE FOOD.
JUST ANOTHER REASON
WE ARE SO GREAT TOGETHER.
- [slurps]
THEY ARE GOOD NOODLES.
HEY, WHO'S THAT CREEPY GUY
OVER THERE
THAT KEEPS LEERING AT US?
- THAT'S TAHNO
AND THE WOLF-BATS--
THE REIGNING CHAMPS
THREE YEARS RUNNING.
DON'T MAKE EYE CONTACT!
[ominous music]
- [laughs]
- UH-OH, HERE HE COMES.
NOW DON'T MESS
WITH THIS GUY.
HE'S A NASTY DUDE.
[gasps]
[slurps]
- WELL, WELL, WELL.
IF IT ISN'T THE FIRE FERRETS--
PRO BENDING'S SADDEST EXCUSE
FOR A TEAM.
TELL ME, HOW DID
A COUPLE OF AMATEURS LIKE YOU
LUCK YOUR WAY
INTO THE TOURNAMENT?
ESPECIALLY,
YOU, UH-VATAR.
- [scoffs]
- YOU KNOW, IF YOU'D LIKE
TO LEARN HOW A REAL PRO BENDS,
I COULD GIVE YOU
SOME PRIVATE LESSONS.
- YOU WANT TO GO TOE-TO-TOE
WITH ME, PRETTY BOY?
- GO FOR IT.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE FIRST SHOT.
- KORRA, DON'T DO IT.
HE'S JUST TRYING
TO BAIT YOU.
YOU HIT HIM,
WE'RE OUT OF THE TOURNAMENT.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- [whistles]
[Naga snarls]
- [whimpers]
[grunts]
[laughter]
- I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYONE RAZZ
TAHNO LIKE THAT.
YOU ARE ONE OF A KIND,
KORRA.
[slurping]
- [belches]
- [loudly belches]
[both laughing]
[romantic music]
♪ ♪
- WHAT KIND OF GAME
ARE YOU PLAYING?
- UH...PRO BENDING.
WE'VE GOT
A QUARTERFINAL MATCH.
- NO, I MEAN WITH BOLIN.
YOU GOT HIM ALL IN A TIZZY,
AND I KNOW
YOU'RE ONLY USING HIM
TO GET BACK AT ME.
- I AM NOT.
WE'RE JUST HAVING FUN TOGETHER.
WHAT DO YOU CARE, ANYWAY?
- I'M LOOKING OUT
FOR MY LITTLE BROTHER.
I DON'T WANT TO SEE
HIS HEART GET BROKEN.
- WAIT A SECOND.
YOU'RE NOT WORRIED ABOUT HIM.
YOU'RE JEALOUS.
YOU DO HAVE FEELINGS FOR ME.
- WHAT?
JEALOUS?
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
- ADMIT IT.
YOU LIKE ME.
- NO, I'M WITH ASAMI.
- YEAH, BUT WHEN
YOU'RE WITH HER,
YOU'RE THINKING ABOUT ME,
AREN'T YOU?
- GET OVER YOURSELF.
- I'M JUST BEING HONEST.
- YOU'RE CRAZY!
- YOU'RE A LIAR!
- HEY, MAKO...
OH.
- EIGHT TEAMS
HAVE BEEN ELIMINATED,
AND EIGHT ADVANCE
INTO THE QUARTERFINALS
WHICH GET UNDER WAY TONIGHT.
THE ROOKIES ARE ABOUT TO TAKE
ON THE FORMER
AND LONGEST-REIGNING CHAMPS--
THE BOAR-Q-PINES.
YOUTH CLASHES
AGAINST EXPERIENCE
IN A BATTLE FOR THE AGES--
OR RATHER, OF THE AGES.
[bell rings]
[fireball whooshing]
- [grunting]
- KORRA DODGES AND--OOH,
SLAMS RIGHT INTO HER TEAMMATE.
[disc whirling]
DOWN GOES MAKO,
AND BOLIN, AND KORRA.
- ROUND ONE GOES
TO THE BOAR-Q-PINES.
[bell rings]
- YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO DEFEND WHILE I ATTACKED!
- I HAD AN OPENING,
SO I TOOK IT!
- WHAT IS UP WITH YOU TWO?
ALL RIGHT, WHATEVER.
JUST PULL IT TOGETHER, GUYS.
[bell rings]
- THE FERRETS LOOKING
TO MOUNT SOME OFFENSE
HERE IN ROUND TWO.
[thud]
- [groans]
- [grunts]
[thud]
[discs whirring]
- BOLIN LETS FLY
A FLURRY OF ATTACKS.
HE'S A ONE MAN
BENDING BATTALION.
- [grunts]
[buzzer rings]
- THE FERRETS HAVING
A TOUGH TIME
FINDING THEIR RHYTHM TONIGHT,
BUT THANKS TO BOLIN,
THEY NARROWLY NOTCH ROUND TWO.
[bell dings]
- [grunts]
- NOT SURE WHAT'S EATIN' THEM,
BUT THIS IS NOT THE SAME TEAM
WHO TOOK OUT THE RABBAROOS.
[buzzer rings]
- ROUND THREE IS A TIE.
WE GO TO A TIE BREAKER
TO DECIDE THE MATCH.
- THE FIRE FERRETS
WIN THE COIN TOSS.
WHICH ELEMENT DO YOU CHOOSE?
- I GOT THIS.
- I KNOW YOU USUALLY
HANDLE THESE,
BUT FRANKLY,
YOUR HEAD'S NOT IN THE GAME.
I'M GOING TO TAKE THIS ONE.
WE CHOOSE EARTH.
- LOOKS LIKE THE EARTH BENDERS
WILL COLLIDE
IN THE TIE BREAKER FACE-OFF.
[bell dings]
BOLIN GOES IN FOR THE GRAPPLE.
CHANG REVERSES.
BOLIN STRIKES FROM MIDAIR,
KNOCKING CHANG
TO THE EDGE OF THE CIRCLE.
ANOTHER STRIKE FROM BOLIN,
AND CHANG'S IN THE DRINK!
[bell dings]
- THE FUTURE INDUSTRIES
FIRE FERRETS
WIN THEIR
QUARTERFINAL MATCH!
OOH, THAT WAS
A CLOSE ONE, FOLKS.
YOUTH TRUMPS EXPERIENCE
TONIGHT.
- WE NEED TO TALK.
LOOK, SOMETIMES YOU CAN BE
SO INFURIATING.
- SAVE YOUR BREATH.
YOU'VE ALREADY MADE IT CLEAR
HOW YOU FEEL ABOUT ME.
- NO, I HAVEN'T.
WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY IS
AS MUCH AS YOU DRIVE ME CRAZY,
I ALSO THINK
YOU'RE PRETTY AMAZING.
- SO YOU DO LIKE ME?
- YES, BUT--
[sighs]
I LIKE ASAMI, TOO.
I DON'T KNOW,
THINGS ARE COMPLICATED.
I'VE BEEN FEELING
REALLY CONFUSED--
- [sobbing]
- BOLIN, THIS ISN'T
WHAT YOU THINK.
- [sobbing]
- GREAT!
LOOK WHAT YOU DID.
- YOU'RE BLAMING ME?
- YOU KISSED ME!
- YOU KISSED ME BACK!
- UUHHH!
- WELL PLAYED, KORRA.
- MORNING, NAROOK.
IS MY BROTHER HERE?
THANKS.
COME ON, WAKE UP.
I'M TAKING YOU
HOME, BRO.
- [sniffles]
DON'T CALL ME THAT.
YOU'RE NOT MY BROTHER.
YOU'RE A BROTHER-BETRAYER.
[sobs]
THE ONLY ONE I CAN
TRUST ANYMORE IS PABU.
PABU LOVES ME.
[Pabu chittering]
- YOU'RE A MESS,
AND WE'VE GOT
THE BIGGEST MATCH
OF OUR LIVES TONIGHT.
LET'S GO.
- NO!
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE
WITH YOU, YOU TRAITOR.
- GUESS WE'LL HAVE TO DO THIS
THE HARD WAY.
- [sobbing]
WHY?
- I TOLD YOU DATING
A TEAMMATE WAS A BAD IDEA.
- YOU'RE A BAD IDEA.
[sobbing]
PUT ME DOWN.
[Pabu chattering]
- YOU CAN'T FIND TWO TEAMS
MORE EVENLY MATCHED
IN AGE, SIZE, AND STRENGTH
THAN THE FIRE FERRETS
AND THE BUZZARD-WASPS.
BELIEVE ME, I'VE LOOKED.
THIS SHOULD BE
A PULSE-POUNDING SEMIFINAL,
FOLKS.
[bell dings]
THE BUZZARD-WASPS OPEN WITH
A FLAWLESSLY EXECUTED COMBO.
- [grunts]
[buzzer rings]
- ALL THREE FERRETS
TAKE AN EARLY VISIT TO ZONE TWO.
AND MAKO'S KNOCKED ALL THE WAY
BACK INTO ZONE THREE!
THE FIRE FERRETS
HAVE BEEN STRUGGLING
TO STAY ALIVE
SINCE THE OPENING BELL.
ALL THREE PLAYERS ARE TOTALLY
OUT OF SYNC TONIGHT.
- [groans]
[buzzer rings]
- OOH, THAT HAS GOT
TO STING!
- [Bolin vomits]
- AND BOLIN LOSES HIS NOODLES.
LITERALLY.
WHICH REMINDS ME,
THIS MATCH IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY OUR SPONSOR,
FLAMEY-O INSTANT NOODLES.
“NOODLEY-EST NOODLES
IN THE UNITED REPUBLIC.”
- [groans]
[buzzer rings]
- THE BUZZARD-WASPS FLY DEEPER
INTO FERRET TERRITORY.
- [groans]
[buzzer rings]
- AND MAKO PLUNGES
INTO THE POOL.
CAN THE FIRE FERRETS
HOLD ON?
THE WASPS HAVE THE FERRETS
BACKED UP TO THE EDGE NOW.
[bell rings]
AND THE FERRETS
ARE BAILED OUT BY THE BELL.
THEY HAD BETTER PULL THEMSELVES
TOGETHER, FOLKS, FOR ROUND TWO.
OTHERWISE THEY CAN KISS
THE FINALS GOOD-BYE.
[bell dings]
- [groans]
[buzzer rings]
HEY!
WATCH IT!
- THE WASPS TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF MAKO'S UNFORCED ERROR,
AND BOLIN'S IN THE POOL!
[water attack splashing]
- AHH!
- OOH, AND A BLATANT HOLD
BY THE AVATAR.
- [blows whistle]
UNNECESSARY ROUGHNESS!
MOVE BACK ONE ZONE!
- I'LL UNNECESSARILY
ROUGH YOU UP!
[water attack splashes]
- AND THE AVATAR IS SLAPPED
WITH A YELLOW FAN.
THE FERRETS ARE THEIR
OWN WORST ENEMY RIGHT NOW.
IT'S JUST SAD
TO WATCH.
WITH THE BUZZARD-WASPS LEADING
TWO ROUNDS TO ZILCH,
THE FERRETS'
ONLY HOPE OF WINNING
IS WITH A KNOCKOUT.
- WELL, I GUESS
THERE'S ALWAYS NEXT YEAR.
- COME ON,
WE STILL HAVE A CHANCE,
EVEN IF IT IS
A SLIM ONE.
- THE WAY WE'RE PLAYING,
WE DON'T EVEN DESERVE
TO BE IN THE FINALS.
- LOOK, IF WE DON'T PULL
TOGETHER AND WORK AS A TEAM,
WE'LL NEVER FORGIVE OURSELVES.
- LET'S JUST GET THIS
OVER WITH.
- THE SOONER THE BETTER.
[bell dings]
[disc whirls]
- [groans]
AH!
- OOH!
[buzzer rings]
- BOLIN'S KNOCKED
INTO ZONE TWO,
FOLLOWED QUICKLY
BY HIS BROTHER.
- [screams]
- AND BOLIN TAKES A ZINGER
TO THE SHOULDER.
LOOKS LIKE
IT'S A CLEAN HIT.
- OW!
- BOLIN!
[buzzer rings]
- [screams]
- MAKO'S IN THE DRINK
AND OUT OF THE MATCH.
AND BOLIN KEEPS PLAYING
WITH ONE GOOD ARM!
I GOTTA HAND IT TO HIM,
THIS KID'S GOT GRIT,
BUT HOW LONG
CAN HE KEEP IT UP?
- AH!
[buzzer rings]
- APPARENTLY, NOT VERY LONG.
THE FERRETS' DREAM OF MAKING IT
TO THE FINALS
NOW RESTS
IN THE AVATAR'S HANDS.
BUT WITH THREE-ON-ONE,
I DON'T LIKE HER ODDS.
- [groans]
- ARE YOU OKAY?
HOW'S YOUR SHOULDER?
- [groans]
IT'S MESSED UP PRETTY BAD.
BUT I THINK I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[buzzer rings]
ARE WE GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT?
- OF COURSE WE ARE.
WE'RE BROTHERS.
WE'LL GET THROUGH
THIS MESS.
I'M SORRY.
- ME, TOO.
GIRLS.
- SERIOUSLY.
- WHAT AN UNBELIEVABLE EFFORT
HERE BY KORRA.
SHE'S DODGING EVERY ELEMENT
THE WASPS THROW AT HER.
- AH!
[buzzer rings]
- THE AVATAR FINALLY GAINS
SOME GROUND,
BUT WITH ONLY
TEN SECONDS REMAINING,
IT MIGHT BE TOO LITTLE,
TOO LATE.
[buzzer rings]
[yelling]
IT'S THE BIG KABOSH!
WHAT AN KNOCKOUT!
[bell dings]
[cheers and applause]
- YES, WE DID IT!
- YEAH!
- IT DIDN'T SEEM POSSIBLE,
FOLKS, BUT THE FIRE FERRETS
ARE HEADED TO THE FINALS.
- [laughs]
- SHOULDER, SHOULDER.
- SORRY.
- THAT WAS PRETTY MUCH THE
COOLEST THING I'VE EVER SEEN.
- THANKS FOR NOT
GIVING UP ON US.
WE NEVER WOULD'VE MADE IT
THIS FAR WITHOUT YOU.
I OWE YOU.
BIG TIME.
- YOU'RE WELCOME.
SO...I KNOW THINGS
ARE CONFUSING RIGHT NOW,
BUT I HOPE WE CAN
STILL BE FRIENDS.
- DEFINITELY.
[ominous music]
- [sniffs]
OH, OH.
YOU BOYS SMELL
SOMETHING IN HERE?
WAIT,
I KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
YEAH, THAT'S THE SCENT
OF LOSERS.
- I HOPE WE SEE YOU
IN THE FINALS.
THEN WE'LL SEE
WHO THE LOSERS REALLY ARE.
- YEAH.
I'M PEEING MY PANTS OVER HERE.
- AND NOW, THE DEFENDING CHAMPS,
THE WHITE FALLS WOLF-BATS!
- [grunts]
- GREAT JOB.
WHAT A COMEBACK, KORRA.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
A HAT TRICK LIKE THAT.
- THANKS,
BUT IF IT HADN'T BEEN
FOR YOU AND YOUR FATHER,
WE WOULDN'T HAVE HAD
THE CHANCE TO PLAY.
SO THANK YOU.
- UH, IF EVERYONE'S DONE WITH
THE LITTLE THANK YOU PARTY,
NEED SOME MEDICAL ATTENTION
OVER HERE.
- OOH, LET ME HELP.
- [screams]
OW! AH!
HAVEN'T YOU HURT ME
ENOUGH, WOMAN?
- RELAX, I'M A HEALER.
I LEARNED FROM KATARA,
THE BEST THERE IS.
- NO, NO, NO,
OHHH...
THAT'S THE STUFF.
- BOLIN, I'M SORRY
I HURT YOUR FEELINGS.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO LET THINGS
GET SO OUT OF HAND.
- AH, I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
BUT WE HAD FUN
TOGETHER, DIDN'T WE?
- I HAD A GREAT TIME,
HONESTLY.
YOU ARE
ONE OF A KIND, BOLIN.
PLEASE, GO ON.
I ENJOY PRAISE.
- YOUR WINNERS...
[bell dings]
THE WOLF-BATS!
- WHAT?
HOW IS IT OVER ALREADY?
- WITH A BRUTAL
ROUND ONE KNOCKOUT,
THE DEFENDING CHAMPS
SECURE THEIR SPOT IN THE FINALS.
I HOPE THE FERRETS
KNOW A GOOD DOCTOR,
BECAUSE THEY'RE GONNA
NEED ONE!
[exotic music]