Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring baIance to the world.
Although the Hundred Year War
has long passed,
we are not living in a time of peace.
These revolutionaries,
who caII themseIves EquaIists,
are not interested in equaIity at aII.
Theyjust want to wage war
against benders.
Chief Beifong was supposed
to protect Republic City,
but she was powerless to stop
Amon's attack on the arena.
She has failed us all.
lf we are to survive these dire times,
our law enforcement
needs new leadership.
l still can't believe
they're shutting this place down.
Yeah, we had some good memories
here, didn't we?
Guys, great news!
You don't have to go back
on the streets.
l talked to Tenzin
and made all the arrangements.
You can come live
on Air Temple lsland with me.
We'd love to, but...
Asami already invited us
to live in her dad's giant mansion!
From here on out,
it's gonna be the lap of luxury for us!
Hey, Korra!
l was hoping you'd stop by.
l was just leaving.
So, l guess l'll see you guys around...
Sometime.
Why not tomorrow?
l'd love to have you
come visit the estate.
l don't know.
l have some Avatar stuff to do.
Come on, Korra!
We all deserve a little rest
and relaxation after all this craziness.
We can swim in Asami's pool.
lt'll be fun.
All right, Pabu.
Great, we'll see you tomorrow.
Looks like our intel was good.
There's enough evidence here
to bury Cabbage Corp for an eternity.
This is an outrage!
l'm innocent!
Yeah, yeah, that's what they all say.
ls it true that Cabbage Corp
is conspiring with the Equalists?
The evidence points in that direction,
but the investigation is ongoing.
For the time being,
we have frozen Mr. Gan-Lan's assets
and are closing Cabbage Corp.
No! Not my Cabbage Corp!
Hey, Korra.
Tahno?
Listen,
l know we're not exactly best friends,
but l'm sorry Amon took your bending.
l've been to the best healers in the city.
Whatever Amon did to me,
it's permanent.
You gotta get him for me.
Mr. Sato,
if you remember anything else about
what you saw during Amon's attack,
be sure to let us know.
l'm happy to help any way l can.
l want these Equalists to pay
for what they've done.
We're ready for you now.
See you around, Avatar.
Earthbending bomb!
Avatar Korra has arrived.
-Hey, Korra!
-Glad you made it!
Welcome to paradise.
Looks like you guys settled right in.
Pretty much. Except someone forgot
to ask her father if we could stay here.
Yeah, but l smoothed it over with him.
lt's easier to ask for forgiveness
than permission.
This is the greatest place in the world!
Watch this, watch this.
Fetch me my towel, good sir!
Yes, Master Bolin.
"Master Bolin."
l love this guy!
Now, pat me dry.
As you wish.
Don't forget Master Pabu.
Wouldn't dream of it, sir.
So, what do you have planned
for us today?
Let me guess. Shopping? Makeovers?
l vote makeovers!
l have something
a little more exciting in mind.
Pretty cool, huh?
Way cooler than a makeover.
This is where Future lndustries
test drives their Sato-mobiles.
Ever been behind the wheel?
The only thing l know how to drive
is a polar bear-dog.
You want me to take you for a spin?
Let's do it.
Yeah!
That was amazing!
l didn't think we'd make it.
Well, you can't be afraid
to mix it up sometimes.
l gotta admit, l had you pegged wrong.
l thought you were kind of prissy.
No offense.
lt's all right.
People usually assume that
l'm "Daddy's helpless little girl,"
but l can handle myself.
l mean, l've been in self-defense
classes since l was this high.
My dad made sure
l would always be able to protect myself.
Smart guy.
Emergency! Emergency!
Coming through!
ls there another bathroom l can use?
We have a ladies' powder room
upstairs.
First door on your right.
You can freshen up in there.
Thanks.
No, no! l assure you,
everything is going exactly as planned.
Yes.
Luckily, the Cabbage Corp investigation
has bought us enough time.
Trust me, by the end of the week,
we'll be ready to strike.
You're leaving?
-But l thought...
-Sorry, l forgot,
l'm supposed to airsit...
l mean babybend...
l mean babysit the Airbender kids.
See you later!
So, you think Mr. Sato manufactured
those gloves for the Equalists,
then framed Cabbage Corp?
That's a bold accusation.
But what proof do you have?
Well, l don't exactly have proof,
but l know what l heard.
Sato's up to something.
He does have the means.
And he has a motive.
That's right.
A motive? What is it?
Twelve years ago, the Agni Kai Triad
robbed Sato's mansion.
A Firebender killed Sato's wife
during the break-in.
That's terrible.
lt was tragic.
lt's possible he's been harboring
anti-bending sentiment all this time.
Maybe we should look at Mr. Sato
a little more closely.
What's going on?
Why are they asking Hiroshi
more questions?
l overheard him on the phone yesterday.
Asami, l don't know how to tell you this,
but l think your father might be involved
with the Equalists.
What? l don't believe this!
You spied on Hiroshi?
What's your problem?
Mr. Sato, we just have a few
follow-up questions for you...
My father is innocent!
Just because we're not benders,
doesn't mean we support
those awful Equalists!
Equalists? ls that what this is about?
l can assure you,
l have nothing to do with those radicals.
Yeah, you don't know
what you're talking about, Korra.
l overheard you on the phone.
You said the Cabbage Corp
investigation bought you time,
and you're getting ready to strike.
Explain that!
This is all just a misunderstanding
resulting from the young Avatar's
overactive imagination.
My number one competitor
was knocked out of the game.
lt's providing me an opportunity
to "strike" the market
with a new line of Sato-mobiles.
lt's just business.
Nothing nefarious.
ln order to put all suspicions to rest,
might we have a look into your factories
and warehouses?
lf you feel it's necessary,
you are welcome to search
all of Future lndustries.
Is it possibIe the presidents of
Cabbage Corp and Future lndustries
both have EquaIist ties?
Or did Hiroshi Sato frame
his longtime rival, Lau Gan-Lan?
Or did Chief Beifong
just pIain arrest the wrong man?
So far the investigation has yielded
no evidence to incriminate Sato.
l can't believe we didn't find anything.
lt would appear Hiroshi is innocent.
Okay, you did your search.
Now you can all leave.
So, l hope you're convinced now.
No, l'm not.
l don't care how cooperative
Hiroshi is being,
l know he's lying.
Why are you doing this?
Are you that jealous of me and Asami?
What? Don't be ridiculous.
That has nothing to do with it.
lf you don't drop this,
consider our friendship over.
l'm sorry.
Hiroshi is not the man you think he is.
l think you guys should hear this.
"lf you want to find the truth,
"meet me under the north end
of the Silk Road Bridge at midnight."
Over here.
Listen, l joined the Equalists
because l believed in what Amon said.
l thought he could make life better
for us non-benders.
But l didn't sign up for this... This war.
What do you have on Hiroshi Sato?
He manufactured those gloves
for the Equalists.
l knew it!
And there are rumors he's working
on something even bigger...
Some new kind of weapon.
We searched all of Future lndustries
and found nothing.
That's because he has a secret factory.
Where?
lt's right underneath the Sato mansion.
Raiding the Sato mansion
is a risky move
with Tarrlok breathing down your neck.
-lf we're wrong...
-l know, l can kiss my job goodbye.
But protecting Republic City
is all l care about.
We can't let Amon get his hands
on this new weapon.
What are you doing here?
We have reason to believe
there's a factory
hidden below the mansion.
l think l would have noticed if there
were a factory underneath my house.
The lies you people come up with
just to persecute my father...
Where is your father?
ln his workshop, behind the house.
Dad?
Hello?
Chief, the estate has been secured.
No one's left the workshop
since we arrived.
Perhaps we just couldn't
see him leaving.
There's a tunnel beneath the workshop,
running deep into the mountainside.
What? There's no tunnel.
Do you think your dad knows
about this tunnel?
l don't understand.
There must be an explanation.
Maybe you don't know everything
about your father.
l'm sorry.
Officers, into the tunnel.
Be cautious.
You three stay up here.
Officer Song, keep an eye on them.
Not your average backyard workshop.
And l'm guessing
those are the new weapons.
Hiroshi was lying, all right.
But where is he?
What was that?
We need to get down there
and see what's going on.
Absolutely not.
You're staying put
until the Chief comes back.
All right, we'll stay put.
But can we wait outside or something?
lt's so dusty in this workshop.
No. We're waiting right here.
Okay, but don't blame me
if l start snee...
lf l start snee...
What's your problem, bub?
l'm about to...
Sorry, pal.
We know you were just doing yourjob.
Yeah, just stay put
until the Chief comes back.
That sounds very familiar, doesn't it?
Why? Because you said it.
Asami, you should stay here.
We'll check it out.
l have to find out the truth
about my father.
l understand.
That's why l'm going down
to find out for you.
Please.
All right.
Be careful.
I'm afraid you won't be abIe
to metalbend that wall, Chief Beifong.
It's soIid pIatinum.
My mecha-tanks are pIatinum as weII.
Not even your renowned mother
could bend a metal so pure.
Hiroshi, l knew you were
a lying, no-good Equalist!
Come out here and...
And do what, young Avatar?
Face the wrath of your bending?
No, I think I'II fight from inside here
where my odds are a IittIe more...
EquaI.
That source was a setup.
You lured us down here!
Guilty as charged.
Korra!
Well, l'd say that was
a near-flawless test run.
Load everyone into the transports
and deliver them to Amon.
No.
Korra was right.
We gotta do something, quick!
Not so fast, boys.
Hello, Mr. Sato.
Wow, what a really swell, scary factory
you have here
under your giant mansion.
Sponsoring our team,
supporting the Avatar...
lt was all just a big cover.
Yes, and the most difficult part
was watching my daughter
traipse around
with a firebending street rat like you.
Dad, stop!
Why?
Sweetie,
l wanted to keep you out of this
for as long as l could,
but now that you know the truth,
please forgive me.
These people...
These benders...
They took away your mother,
the love of my life.
They've ruined the world!
But with Amon, we can fix it
and build a perfect world together.
We can help people like us,
everywhere!
Join me, Asami.
No.
l love you, Dad.
Let's get out of here!
My Metalbenders are on their way
to Amon, and it's all my fault.
Tarrlok's right, l failed as chief.
First thing in the morning,
l'm handing in my resignation.
No! You can't give up like this.
l'm not giving up.
l'm going to find my officers
and take Amon down.
But l'm going to do it my way,
outside the law.
l'm sorry l didn't believe you.
But Asami's dad being an Equalist
is not an easy thing to believe.
-Even now.
-l know.
l'm sorry this whole thing happened.
So, does your offer to live
at the Air Temple still stand?
Of course it does.
And Asami's welcome, too.
Thank you so much.
After everything she's been through,
she's going to need you, Mako.