- EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR...
WATER...
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN
MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
- REPUBLIC CITY IS AT WAR.
AFTER DISCOVERING THAT HER
FATHER, HIROSHI SATO,
IS WORKING WITH THE ENEMY,
ASAMI TURNS AGAINST HIM.
AND FOLLOWING ANOTHER DEFEAT AT
THE HANDS OF THE EQUALISTS,
LIN BEIFONG RESIGNS
AS CHIEF OF POLICE.
WITH THE EQUALIST
ARMY GROWING STRONGER,
WHO WILL HELP
THE AVATAR STOP AMON
AND RESTORE BALANCE TO THE CITY?
[Pabu chirps]
- YOU'RE FINALLY HERE!
WELCOME TO AIR TEMPLE ISLAND!
YOUR NEW HOME.
- YES, WELCOME TO MY DOMAIN.
- WELL AREN'T YOU SWEET,
LITTLE MONK CHILD.
[Pabu chirps]
- WHAT'S THAT FUZZY CREATURE?
- THAT IS A FIRE FERRET.
AN ARBOREAL MAMMAL COMMON
TO THE BAMBOO FORESTS
OF THE CENTRAL EARTH KINGDOM.
- [gasps]
HE'S CUTE!
[Pabu hisses]
- [laughs]
YIP-YIP. FLY SKY-BISON! FLY!
- THANKS FOR SENDING
THE AIR ACOLYTES
TO HELP US WITH THE MOVE.
- YES, THEY'VE BEEN AMAZING.
SUCH TIRELESS WORKERS.
- OH, I THOUGHT YOU WERE ONLY
BRINGING A FEW THINGS.
- TRUST ME, IT COULD
HAVE BEEN WORSE.
- NO PROBLEM. EVERYONE HERE
WANTS YOU GUYS TO FEEL WELCOME.
[Pabu chirps]
- ♪ LA LA LA LA ♪
- YOU'RE PRETTY.
CAN I HAVE SOME OF YOUR HAIR?
- LOOKS LIKE I HAVE
SOME COMPETITION.
- AND NOW FOR THE GRAND TOUR.
THE FLYING BISONS SLEEP IN THOSE
CAVES DOWN THERE.
AND THAT'S THE TEMPLE
GRANDPA AANG BUILT.
AND THAT'S THE GREENHOUSE WHERE
WE GROW THE VEGETABLES WE EAT.
- I HAVE A COUPLE OF QUESTIONS.
IS THIS AN
ALL-VEGETARIAN ISLAND?
IS THAT WHERE YOU
TRAIN AIR-BENDING?
DO WE HAVE TO WEAR
AIR ACOLYTE CLOTHES?
DO WE EACH GET
OUR OWN SKY-BISON?
AND FINAL QUESTION: HOW MANY
TREES ARE ON THIS ISLAND?
- YES, YES, NO, NO, 10,552.
- SO WHERE ARE WE
GONNA BE STAYING?
- YOU'RE A BOY.
BOYS HAVE TO STAY
ON THE BOYS' SIDE.
- I'D BE HAPPY TO SHOW YOU TO
THE MEN'S DORMITORY.
- I'M A BOY.
- MEELO, WHY DON'T YOU GO WITH
THE BOYS TOO?
- WE SHALL MEET AGAIN SOON,
BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
- IKKI AND I WILL TAKE YOU TO
YOUR ROOM, THIS WAY.
- ASAMI, DID YOU KNOW
KORRA LIKES MAKO?
- [enraged scream]
- OH...UH, NO, I WASN'T
COMPLETELY AWARE OF THAT.
- HEY!
- RUN ALONG, IKKI.
- [sighs]
[growls]
SO...
HERE'S YOUR ROOM.
I KNOW THIS IS A LITTLE RUSTIC
COMPARED TO WHAT YOU'RE USED TO.
- I THINK IT'S REALLY CHARMING.
AND THE BEST PART ABOUT IT?
NOTHING HERE REMINDS
ME OF MY FATHER.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR HOSPITALITY.
[knock on door]
- IKKI, I SWEAR IF YOU DON'T
LEAVE US ALONE, I'M GONNA--
UH, TENZIN. COME RIGHT IN.
- GOOD DAY, LADIES.
ASAMI, WELCOME TO THE ISLAND.
- THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
- BEIFONG'S REPLACEMENT,
SAIKHAN,
IS GOING TO BE INDUCTED AS THE
NEW CHIEF OF POLICE LATER.
I THINK WE SHOULD BOTH BE THERE.
- IT WAS AN HONOR SERVING UNDER
CHIEF BEIFONG FOR SO MANY YEARS,
AND I WISH HER
A SPEEDY RECOVERY.
IT IS WITH GREAT HUMILITY
THAT I TAKE HER PLACE
AS THE NEW CHIEF OF POLICE.
REPUBLIC CITY IS FACING A THREAT
LIKE NONE THE WORLD
HAS EVER SEEN.
BUT THERE IS ONE MAN
WHO HAS BEEN EFFECTIVE
AGAINST AMON'S REVOLUTION:
COUNCILMAN TARRLOK.
THAT IS WHY FOR ALL MATTERS
INVOLVING THE EQUALISTS,
I WILL REPORT DIRECTLY TO HIM.
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT WILL LEND
ANY AND ALL AVAILABLE RESOURCES
TO THE COUNCILMAN
AND HIS TASK FORCE
UNTIL WE QUELL THIS INSURGENCY.
- WHAT IS THAT WEASEL-SNAKE
TARRLOK UP TO NOW?
- TARRLOK, I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU DID TO GET CHIEF SAIKHAN
IN YOUR POCKET, BUT I HIGHLY
DOUBT IT WAS LEGAL.
- OH, TENZIN, ALWAYS THE
CONSPIRACY THEORIST.
DID YOU EVER CONSIDER SAIKHAN
SIMPLY RECOGNIZES MY TALENTS
AND WANTS WHAT IS
BEST FOR THIS CITY?
- [scoffs]
- WELL, AVATAR KORRA,
LONG TIME, NO SEE.
NOW THAT YOUR LITTLE PRO-BENDING
DISTRACTIONS ARE OVER,
I LOOK FORWARD TO YOUR RETURN TO
MY TASK FORCE.
- [scoffs]
FORGET IT.
THERE'S NO WAY I'M REJOINING
YOUR VANITY PROJECT.
- THAT IS UNFORTUNATE TO HEAR.
BUT I'M SURE YOU'LL COME TO YOUR
SENSES AS YOU HAVE IN THE PAST.
- DON'T HOLD YOUR BREATH, BUB.
YOU KNOW, TENZIN'S BEEN RIGHT
ABOUT YOU ALL ALONG.
YOU PLAYED ME,
YOU PLAYED BEIFONG,
AND NOW YOU'RE PLAYING
THE NEW CHIEF TOO.
WELL I GOT NEWS FOR YOU.
YOU NEED ME,
BUT I DON'T NEED YOU.
I'M THE AVATAR.
- YOU'RE NOT,
IN FACT, THE AVATAR.
YOU ARE MERELY A HALF-BAKED
AVATAR-IN-TRAINING.
WHICH REMINDS ME, HOW IS YOUR
AIRBENDING GOING?
MADE ANY SIGNIFICANT
PROGRESS WITH THAT?
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
IF YOU WILL NOT BE
PART OF MY TASK FORCE,
THEN YOU HAD BEST
STAY OUT OF MY WAY.
[sky-bison growls]
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME.
I'VE MEMORIZED NEARLY ALL OF THE
PRACTICE FORMS,
BUT I STILL CAN'T PRODUCE
A SINGLE MEASLY PUFF OF AIR.
I'M A FAILURE.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT.
YOU JUST NEED TO WORK THROUGH
THIS AIRBENDING BLOCK.
- AMAZING ADVICE.
I'LL GET RIGHT ON THAT.
- I WASN'T FINISHED YET.
YOU SEE, AANG NOT ONLY HAD HIS
BENDING TEACHERS,
BUT ALSO HIS PAST LIVES
TO CALL UPON FOR GUIDANCE.
HAVE YOU EVER MADE CONTACT WITH
YOUR PAST LIVES?
- NO, OF COURSE I HAVEN'T.
DIDN'T YOU GET THE MEMO
FROM THE WHITE LOTUS?
I'M A SPIRITUAL FAILURE TOO.
- YOU MAY HAVE MADE A CONNECTION
WITHOUT REALIZING IT.
PERHAPS SOMETHING YOU
MISTOOK AS A DREAM.
- MAYBE.
I HAD A FEW WEIRD
HALLUCINATIONS.
BUT I HARDLY EVEN REMEMBER THEM.
- AND DID YOU SEE ANY
OF THE PREVIOUS
AVATARS IN THESE VISIONS?
- I SAW AANG.
IT SEEMED LIKE HE
WAS IN TROUBLE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK IT MEANS?
- HMM, I DON'T KNOW.
BUT I URGE YOU TO MEDITATE
ON THESE VISIONS.
I BELIEVE AANG'S SPIRIT MUST BE
TRYING TO TELL YOU SOMETHING.
- [cries]
- KORRA?
YOU OUT HERE?
[Pabu chirps]
KORRA!
[Pabu coos]
THERE YOU ARE.
ARE YOU OKAY?
- I'M FINE.
- COME ON.
WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU CAN TELL US.
- [sighs]
HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO SAVE THE CITY
WHEN I CAN'T EVEN
LEARN AIRBENDING?
I'M THE WORST AVATAR EVER.
I JUST FEEL ALONE.
- NO, THAT'S NONSENSE.
YOU ARE AMAZING.
- YEAH, AND REMEMBER,
AANG HADN'T MASTERED
ALL THE ELEMENTS WHEN HE WAS
BATTLING THE FIRE NATION.
HE WAS JUST A LITTLE KID.
- AND HE WASN'T ALONE.
HE HAD HIS FRIENDS TO HELP HIM.
LOOK, THE ARENA MIGHT BE SHUT
DOWN, BUT WE'RE STILL A TEAM.
THE NEW TEAM AVATAR!
- WE'VE GOT YOUR BACK, KORRA.
AND WE CAN SAVE
THE CITY. TOGETHER.
- YEAH.
LET'S DO IT.
- [flatulence]
YEAH, LET'S DO IT!
[flatulence]
WHAT ARE WE DOING?
[all laugh]
- GET READY, REPUBLIC CITY.
YOU ARE ABOUT TO BE PATROLLED BY
TEAM AVATAR.
- ASAMI, YOU ALWAYS KNOW HOW TO
ACCESSORIZE YOUR OUTFITS.
- I FIGURE ONE WAY
TO FIGHT EQUALISTS
IS TO USE AN EQUALIST'S WEAPON.
[electricity crackles]
- ALL RIGHT.
LET'S RIDE.
- NAGA, AWAY!
all: WHOA! OOF!
- ALL RIGHT, SCRATCH THAT.
ANY OTHER IDEAS?
- HMM, I THINK
I HAVE THE ANSWER.
[door creaks]
[engine roars]
[tires screech]
YOU THINK THIS'LL DO?
- I LIKE THE NEW
TEAM AVATAR'S STYLE.
- [over radio]
UNIT 216?
CANCEL THAT 1058
AT HARMONY TOWER.
COME BACK TO THE STATION. OVER.
- MY DAD HAD POLICE SCANNERS
INSTALLED IN ALL OF HIS CARS.
I GUESS NOW I KNOW WHY.
- [over radio]
CALLING ALL UNITS.
LEVEL FOUR ALERT.
JAIL BREAK AT HEADQUARTERS.
OFFICERS DOWN. ELECTROCUTED.
CHI-BLOCKERS AND EQUALIST
CONVICTS ARE STILL AT LARGE,
ARMED AND DANGEROUS.
LAST SEEN HEADING EAST.
- WHOA.
- I REPEAT, LEVEL FOUR ALERT.
EQUALIST JAIL BREAK.
[tires screech]
- CHI-BLOCKERS! THAT'S THEM!
- LET'S GET 'EM.
[tires screech]
KORRA, BOLIN!
GIVE ME A RAMP. NOW!
all: WHOA!
- GAH!
[gas hisses]
- HELP ME OUT,
WE'VE GOTTA MAKE THIS TURN.
THEY DON'T KNOW
WE MADE THE TURN.
OKAY, GET READY...
[fire crackles]
- OOF! AAGH!
[groans]
[electricity crackles]
- [screams]
- [grunts]
[grunts]
[electricity crackles]
[screams]
[tires screech]
[sirens wail]
- AVATAR KORRA, WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
- OH, HEY, TARRLOK.
NICE OF YOU TO SHOW UP FINALLY.
HERE, WE CAPTURED THE ESCAPED
CONVICTS FOR YOU.
- WHAT YOU DID WAS TEAR UP
THE CITY AND IMPEDE
THE REAL AUTHORITIES IN THEIR
PURSUIT OF THESE CRIMINALS.
- HMM, THAT'S FUNNY.
I DIDN'T SEE YOUR
LITTLE TASK FORCE OR THE COPS
THE WHOLE TIME.
IF IT WASN'T FOR TEAM AVATAR,
THEY WOULD HAVE GOTTEN AWAY.
- THIS IS YOUR LAST WARNING.
STAY OUT OF MY WAY.
[engine starts]
REPUBLIC CITY STANDS
AS A BEACON OF FREEDOM,
BUT THE EQUALISTS ARE USING THAT
FREEDOM TO TEAR IT DOWN.
THE LAW I HAVE PROPOSED WOULD
MAKE IT ILLEGAL FOR ANYONE
TO BE A MEMBER OF THE EQUALISTS
OR EVEN BE ASSOCIATED WITH THEM.
IT ALSO PUTS INTO
EFFECT A CURFEW,
ENSURING ALL NON-BENDERS ARE IN
THEIR OWN HOMES BY NIGHTFALL.
- THIS IS GOING
TOO FAR, TARRLOK.
YOU CAN'T PUNISH ALL NON-BENDERS
FOR THE ACTIONS OF A FEW.
- THAT KIND OF COWARDICE
WILL CAUSE OUR CITY
TO FALL INTO AMON'S HANDS.
WE MUST PASS THIS LAW.
ALL IN FAVOR?
- [angry sigh]
- [over radio]
ALL AVAILABLE UNITS,
PLEASE RESPOND TO THE 5600 BLOCK
OF DRAGON FLATS BOROUGH.
EQUALISTS HAVE TAKEN
TO THE STREETS.
CONSIDER THEM ARMED
AND DANGEROUS.
PROCEED WITH CAUTION.
- I CALL FRONT!
- AFTER YOU.
- WHAT A GENTLEMAN.
THANKS.
WHY IS THE POWER OUT?
[distant murmurs]
[angry chattering]
- WAIT A SECOND, THESE PEOPLE
AREN'T ARMED OR DANGEROUS.
- SURE DOESN'T LOOK THAT WAY.
- ALL NON-BENDERS, RETURN TO
YOUR HOMES IMMEDIATELY.
- YEAH, AS SOON AS YOU TURN OUR
POWER BACK ON.
all: YEAH!
- DISPERSE OR YOU WILL
ALL BE ARRESTED.
- YOU BENDERS CAN'T
TREAT US THIS WAY.
- MOMMY, LOOK.
IT'S THE AVATAR.
- PLEASE, HELP US.
YOU'RE OUR AVATAR TOO.
- EVERYONE PLEASE STAY CALM.
I'M GONNA PUT A STOP TO THIS.
TARRLOK.
YOU NEED TO TURN THE POWER BACK
ON AND LEAVE THESE PEOPLE ALONE.
- AVATAR KORRA, YOU AND YOUR
PLAYMATES HAVE NO BUSINESS HERE.
- WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE RIGHT
TO TREAT THESE
INNOCENT PEOPLE
LIKE CRIMINALS.
- THIS IS AN EQUALIST RALLY.
THERE'S NOTHING
INNOCENT ABOUT IT.
- THEY'RE NOT EQUALISTS.
THEY'RE JUST NORMAL PEOPLE WHO
WANT THEIR RIGHTS BACK.
- THEY ARE THE ENEMY.
ROUND UP ALL THESE EQUALISTS.
[scared chattering]
[all scream]
- STOP!
- [growls]
- [grunts]
HEY, LET ME GO.
- YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
- WHAT? YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
- ACTUALLY, I CAN.
SHE'S A NON-BENDER
OUT PAST CURFEW
AND HER FATHER IS A KNOWN
EQUALIST CONSPIRATOR.
- LET HER GO.
- ARREST HIM AND HIS BROTHER.
- TARRLOK!
- UNLESS YOU WANT TO JOIN YOUR
FRIENDS IN PRISON,
I SUGGEST YOU PUT THOSE DOWN AND
GO BACK TO THE AIR TEMPLE.
- KORRA, LISTEN TO HIM.
IT'S NOT WORTH IT.
- WE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
- DON'T WORRY, I'LL CALL TENZIN.
HE CAN GET YOU OUT.
- SO SAD TO SEE YOUR LITTLE
"TEAM AVATAR" BROKEN UP.
YOU HAD A GOOD RUN.
- THIS ISN'T OVER, TARRLOK.
- OH, I BELIEVE IT IS.
TAKE THEM AWAY.
[sirens wail]
- HEY!
- I CAME AS FAST AS I COULD.
ARE YOUR FRIENDS ALL RIGHT?
- I DON'T KNOW.
THESE KNUCKLEHEADS WON'T TELL ME
ANYTHING.
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF THIS.
- [nervous gasp]
- SAIKHAN, A WORD PLEASE.
- COUNCILMAN TENZIN, I'M PRETTY
SWAMPED AT THE MOMENT.
CAN THIS WAIT?
- NO, IT CANNOT.
THREE OF AVATAR KORRA'S FRIENDS
WERE WRONGLY ARRESTED TONIGHT.
I'D LIKE YOU TO RELEASE THEM
IMMEDIATELY.
- THEY'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
THEY WERE INTERFERING WITH
POLICE BUSINESS.
- YOUR SO-CALLED "POLICE
BUSINESS" WAS ROUNDING UP
INNOCENT PEOPLE AND CLAIMING
THEY WERE EQUALISTS.
THEY SHOULD BE RELEASED TOO.
- ALL EQUALIST SUSPECTS ARE
BEING DETAINED INDEFINITELY.
THEY'LL BE FREED IF
AND WHEN THE TASK FORCE
DEEMS THEY ARE NO
LONGER A THREAT.
- THOSE PEOPLE ARE ENTITLED TO
DUE PROCESS UNDER THE LAW.
- YOU'LL HAVE TO TAKE THAT UP
WITH COUNCILMAN TARRLOK.
- OH, I PLAN TO.
AT THE COUNCIL MEETING,
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
- YOU'RE OFFICIALLY THE WORST
CHIEF OF POLICE EVER!
- CALM DOWN, KORRA.
I'LL GET THIS SORTED OUT.
WE JUST NEED TO BE PATIENT.
BUT YOU REALLY
ARE THE WORST! EVER!
- [growls]
WAKE UP, NAGA.
LET'S GO.
WAIT FOR ME HERE, GIRL.
DON'T WORRY, I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[door crashes open]
YOU AND I NEED TO TALK.
- ARE ANY OF THE OTHER COUNCIL
MEMBERS HERE?
- I BELIEVE EVERYONE HAS GONE
HOME FOR THE NIGHT.
- THEN YOU SHOULD DO THE SAME.
- ARE YOU SURE, SIR?
- LEAVE US.
[door closes]
YOU OBVIOUSLY HAVE SOMETHING ON
YOUR MIND.
SPIT IT OUT.
- DON'T YOU SEE?
YOU'RE DOING EXACTLY WHAT AMON
SAYS IS WRONG WITH BENDERS.
YOU'RE USING YOUR POWER TO
OPPRESS AND INTIMIDATE PEOPLE.
- AND YOU DON'T?
- OF...OF COURSE NOT.
- ISN'T THAT WHAT
YOU CAME HERE TO DO?
INTIMIDATE ME INTO RELEASING
YOUR FRIENDS?
SEE, THAT'S WHAT I ADMIRE
ABOUT YOU, KORRA.
YOUR WILLINGNESS
TO GO TO EXTREMES
IN ORDER TO GET WHAT YOU WANT.
IT IS A QUALITY WE BOTH SHARE.
- YOU AND I ARE NOTHING ALIKE.
- LOOK, I'LL MAKE YOU A DEAL.
YOU FALL IN LINE
AND DO WHAT I SAY
AND I'LL RELEASE YOUR FRIENDS.
- THAT'S WHY YOU ARRESTED THEM?
TO GET TO ME?
- I NEED YOUR ANSWER.
- NO.
YOU MIGHT BE ABLE TO MANIPULATE
CHIEF SAIKHAN INTO
FOLLOWING YOU,
BUT IT WON'T WORK ON ME.
- YOU WILL REGRET THAT DECISION.
- YOU NEED TO BE STOPPED.
YOU'RE JUST AS BAD AS AMON.
- I'VE TRIED TO WORK
WITH YOU, KORRA,
BUT YOU'VE MADE IT IMPOSSIBLE.
- [grunts]
- UGH!
[ice shatters]
[clothes tear]
- AAH!
AAH!
[grunts]
- OOF!
[screams]
- STILL THINK I'M
A HALF-BAKED AVATAR?
- [screams]
- [grunts]
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO NOW?
YOU'RE ALL OUT OF WATER, PAL.
- [nervous grunts]
- [growls]
[groans]
- YOU'RE IN MY WAY, AVATAR.
AND YOU NEED TO BE REMOVED.
- [grunts]
YOU'RE--YOU'RE A BLOODBENDER?
- VERY OBSERVANT.
- IT'S NOT A FULL MOON.
HOW--HOW ARE YOU DOING THIS?
- THERE ARE A LOT OF THINGS
YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT ME.
- UGH!
OOF!
[groans]
WHERE ARE YOU TAKING ME?
- SOMEWHERE NO ONE
WILL FIND YOU.
SAY GOODBYE TO REPUBLIC CITY,
AVATAR KORRA.
YOU'LL NEVER SEE IT AGAIN.
- [growls]
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
LET ME OUT!
[screams]