- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[exciting music]
♪ ♪
- THE AVATAR
HAS BEEN ABDUCTED!
AFTER TARRLOK ARRESTED
HER FRIENDS,
KORRA CONFRONTED THE COUNCILMAN
IN HIS CHAMBERS.
BUT THE HEATED ARGUMENT
QUICKLY TURNED
INTO AN ALL-OUT
BENDING BATTLE.
DESPERATE TO SAVE HIMSELF,
TARRLOK REVEALED
HIS ABILITY TO BLOODBEND
AND TOOK KORRA
FAR FROM REPUBLIC CITY.
WILL THE AVATAR'S FRIENDS
FIND HER
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE?
[mystical music]
♪ ♪
[door creaks open]
[footsteps approach]
- [groaning]
[groaning loudly]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TARRLOK!
YOU CAN'T KEEP ME
IN HERE FOREVER!
[banging]
[engine turns over]
[phone rings]
- [sighs]
[ringing continues]
- [grunts]
WHO IS THIS?
IT'S 6:00 IN THE MORNING.
THIS BETTER BE IMPORTANT.
- COUNCILMAN TENZIN HERE.
WHAT?
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT WAS KORRA DOING
AT CITY HALL?
- AS I TOLD CHIEF SAIKHAN,
KORRA CAME TO MY OFFICE
LATE LAST NIGHT.
SHE WAS UPSET
THAT I ARRESTED HER FRIENDS.
SHE ASKED ME
TO RELEASE THEM,
AND THAT'S WHEN
THE EQUALISTS ATTACKED.
I TRIED TO PROTECT KORRA,
BUT WE WERE OUTNUMBERED.
THEN I WAS ELECTROCUTED.
[electricity crackling]
[screaming]
WHEN I CAME TO,
THE POLICE HAD ARRIVED,
BUT KORRA WAS GONE.
[sighs]
I'M SO SORRY.
CHIEF SAIKHAN, MOBILIZE
THE ENTIRE POLICE FORCE.
WE HAVE TO FIND
THE AVATAR.
[static]
- WE INTERRUPT
YOUR REGULARLY SCHEDULED
BROADCAST
TO BRING YOU
THIS SPECIAL REPORT.
LATE LAST NIGHT,
EQUALISTS ATTACKED CITY HALL...
[volume increases]
SUBDUING COUNCILMAN TARRLOK
AND CAPTURING AVATAR KORRA.
DETAILS ARE STILL
COMING IN, BUT--
[radio clicks off]
- [groans]
- HOPE YOU GOT
ENOUGH BEAUTY REST.
COME ON.
I'M BUSTING YOU OUT.
- THANKS. I OWE YOU.
[dripping sound]
- ARE YOU DONE YET?
- COVER YOUR EARS.
I CAN'T GO
WITH YOU LISTENING.
- AGH.
[footsteps approach]
ASAMI!
- AAH!
A LITTLE PRIVACY, PLEASE?
- ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I'M FINE.
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
- HATE TO BREAK UP
YOUR LOVERS' REUNION,
BUT KORRA'S IN TROUBLE.
AMON CAPTURED HER.
- NO.
NO, SHE CAN'T BE GONE.
- COME ON.
WE HAVE AN AVATAR TO RESCUE.
[zipper zips]
- YAH!
- YOUR FLY WAS DOWN.
- THANKS FOR CATCHING THAT.
[wind whispering]
[banging]
- [grunting]
SOMEBODY!
HELP!
PLEASE!
[panting]
PLEASE.
- I URGE YOU TO MEDITATE
ON THESE VISIONS.
I BELIEVE AANG'S SPIRIT
IS TRYING
TO TELL YOU SOMETHING.
- [breathes deeply]
[many footsteps approach]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE,
AANG?
I TOLD YOU
I HAVE THIS UNDER CONTROL.
- UNDER NORMAL CIRCUMSTANCES,
I WOULDN'T GET INVOLVED.
BUT IF WHAT THOSE VICTIMS SAID
IS TRUE,
WE'RE NOT DEALING
WITH A NORMAL CRIMINAL.
- FINE.
FOLLOW ME, TWINKLE TOES.
- TOPH, I'M 40 YEARS OLD.
YOU THINK YOU COULD STOP
WITH THE NICKNAMES?
- 'FRAID NOT.
IT'S OVER.
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST, YAKONE.
- WHAT IS REPUBLIC CITY
COMING TO?
USED TO BE A MAN
COULD ENJOY HIS LUNCH IN PEACE.
[grunts]
WHAT'S THE BIG IDEA?
- WE HAVE DOZENS
OF WITNESSES, YAKONE.
WE KNOW WHAT YOU ARE.
- TAKE HIM AWAY.
- I'VE BEATEN EVERY
TRUMPED-UP CHARGE
YOU YAHOOS HAVE BROUGHT
AGAINST ME.
AND I'LL BEAT THIS ONE TOO.
- WHOA.
I FINALLY CONNECTED
WITH YOU, AANG.
BUT WHAT ARE YOU TRYING
TO TELL ME?
A WAY OUT OF THIS BOX
WOULD BE NICE.
[breathes deeply]
[footsteps approach]
- I HAVE TO GO.
CALL ME BACK THE MINUTE
YOU HEAR ANYTHING.
LIN, WHAT--WHAT ARE--
WHAT ARE YOU--
YOU SHOULD BE
IN THE HOSPITAL.
AND YOU THREE,
YOU SHOULD BE IN PRISON!
- I FIGURED YOU COULD USE
OUR HELP FINDING KORRA.
- DO YOU HAVE ANY LEADS?
- I'VE BEEN ON THE PHONE
ALL MORNING,
BUT NOTHING YET.
- WE NEED NAGA.
SHE CAN TRACK KORRA.
- I'M AFRAID HER POLAR-BEAR DOG
IS MISSING AS WELL.
- THEN WHERE DO WE START?
- MY GUESS IS THE EQUALISTS
ARE HIDING UNDERGROUND,
IN THE MAZE OF TUNNELS
BENEATH THE CITY.
- UNDERGROUND...
JUST LIKE MY FATHER'S
SECRET FACTORY.
FIGURES.
- YEAH, YEAH,
THAT MAKES SENSE.
WHEN THOSE CHI-BLOCKERS
HAD ME IN THEIR TRUCK,
IT SOUNDED LIKE
WE DROVE INTO A TUNNEL.
- I KNOW WHERE
TO START LOOKING.
COME ON.
- WHEREVER AMON
IS KEEPING KORRA,
I BET THAT'S WHERE
MY OFFICERS ARE TOO.
- LET'S BRING THEM
ALL HOME, LIN.
[creature growls]
- THE TRUCK WITH BOLIN TOOK OFF
DOWN THIS ALLEY.
- WHICH WAY?
- HMM, THIS WAY
KINDA SMELLS FAMILIAR.
- THERE'S A TUNNEL NEARBY.
- THERE!
- MOTORCYCLE TRACKS.
- KORRA HAS TO BE
IN THERE...
SOMEWHERE.
- LET'S TRY THIS WAY.
- AND WHAT IF KORRA'S
NOT DOWN THERE?
- THEN WE PICK ANOTHER TUNNEL
UNTIL WE FIND HER.
- HEY, IS MAKO ALL RIGHT?
HE SEEMS REALLY WORRIED
ABOUT KORRA.
- YEAH, WE ALL ARE.
- I KNOW, BUT--
HE'S YOUR BROTHER.
DO YOU THINK
HE LIKES KORRA
AS MORE THAN JUST A FRIEND?
- [laughs]
WHAT? NO!
THAT'S JUST GOSSIP.
WHERE'D YOU HEAR THAT?
CRAZY TALK IS COMING
OUT OF YOUR MOUTH RIGHT NOW.
[chuckles]
- WHAT DO YOU KNOW, BOLIN?
COME ON, SPILL IT.
- NOTHING!
I MEAN, THERE WAS THIS
ONE TIME DURING THE TOURNAMENT
WHEN MAKO
AND KORRA KISSED, BUT--
- THEY KISSED?
- BELIEVE ME,
I WAS UPSET TOO.
BUT I'M OVER IT.
I DON'T THINK
IT MEANT ANYTHING.
- I DOUBT THAT.
[roaring engine approaches]
- HIDE!
[tires squeal]
[engine slows]
- THAT TRAM GOES
TO THE TRAINING CAMP.
- EVERYTHING WAS DELIVERED
TO THE PRISON, SIR.
- THAT'S WHERE THEY MUST BE
KEEPING KORRA.
- WE NEED TO GET
DOWN THAT TUNNEL.
[alarm buzzes]
- IT'S EMPTY.
- YEAH, I CAN SEE THAT.
both: AGH!
[footsteps approach]
- YOU TWO,
KEEP AN EYE ON THEM.
[sword blade slashes]
MY OFFICERS ARE INSIDE.
- WHAT ABOUT KORRA?
- I DON'T SEE HER YET.
- AVATAR KORRA--
WHERE ARE YOU KEEPING HER?
- CHIEF BEIFONG?
- I'M TOO LATE.
THAT MONSTER ALREADY TOOK
YOUR BENDING, DIDN'T HE?
I'M SO SORRY.
COME ON.
LET'S GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
- I'LL ASK YOU
ONE MORE TIME.
WHERE IS SHE?
- WE DON'T HAVE THE AVATAR.
AND THE EQUALISTS DIDN'T ATTACK
CITY HALL.
TARRLOK'S LYING.
- WHAT?
- [gasps]
- I SCANNED
THE ENTIRE PRISON.
KORRA'S NOT HERE.
- WHY WOULD TARRLOK
MAKE UP A STORY
ABOUT GETTING ATTACKED?
- BECAUSE HE HAS KORRA.
HE FOOLED US ALL.
[alarm blaring]
- LET'S GO, PEOPLE!
TRY TO CHI-BLOCK THAT,
FOOLS!
- WE GOT MORE COMPANY.
[metal creaks]
HANG ON!
[all groaning]
- YAKONE HAS RULED
REPUBLIC CITY'S CRIMINAL EMPIRE
FOR YEARS.
YET HE HAS ALWAYS MANAGED
TO STAY
OUT OF THE LAW'S REACH
UNTIL NOW.
YOU WILL HEAR TESTIMONY
FROM DOZENS OF HIS VICTIMS.
AND THEY WILL TELL YOU
YAKONE HAS MAINTAINED
HIS GRIP ON THE UNDERWORLD
BY USING AN ABILITY THAT
HAS BEEN ILLEGAL FOR DECADES--
BLOODBENDING.
- THE PROSECUTION'S
ENTIRE CASE
IS BUILT UPON
THE MAKE-BELIEVE NOTION
THAT MY CLIENT IS ABLE
TO BLOODBEND AT WILL,
AT ANY TIME,
ON ANY DAY.
I REMIND THE COUNCIL
THAT BLOODBENDING
IS AN INCREDIBLY RARE SKILL,
AND IT CAN ONLY BE PERFORMED
DURING A FULL MOON.
YET THE WITNESSES
WILL CLAIM
THAT MY CLIENT USED BLOODBENDING
AT EVERY OTHER TIME
EXCEPT DURING A FULL MOON.
IT WOULD BE A MOCKERY
OF JUSTICE
TO CONVICT A MAN
OF A CRIME
THAT IS IMPOSSIBLE
TO COMMIT.
- COUNCILMAN SOKKA
WILL NOW DELIVER THE VERDICT.
- IN MY YEARS,
I HAVE ENCOUNTERED
PEOPLE BORN
WITH RARE AND UNIQUE
BENDING ABILITIES.
I ONCE BESTED A MAN
WITH MY TRUSTY BOOMERANG
WHO WAS ABLE TO FIREBEND
WITH HIS MIND.
WHY, EVEN METALBENDING
WAS CONSIDERED IMPOSSIBLE
FOR ALL OF HISTORY,
UNTIL OUR ESTEEMED
CHIEF OF POLICE,
TOPH BEIFONG,
SINGLE-HANDEDLY DEVELOPED
THE SKILL.
THE OVERWHELMING AMOUNT
OF TESTIMONY AND EVIDENCE
HAS CONVINCED THIS COUNCIL
THAT YAKONE IS ONE
OF THESE UNIQUE BENDERS.
AND HE EXPLOITED
HIS ABILITY
TO COMMIT
THESE HEINOUS CRIMES.
WE FIND YAKONE GUILTY
OF ALL CHARGES
AND SENTENCE HIM
TO LIFE IN PRISON.
[gavel bangs]
- HMPH!
[indistinct murmuring]
- [groaning]
- [laughing]
- [breathing shakily]
- THANK YOU ALL FOR MEETING US
ON SUCH SHORT NOTICE.
- CHIEF.
- LIN.
[footsteps approach]
- HAVE YOU NEWS
OF AVATAR KORRA?
- WE DO.
YOU KIDNAPPED HER, TARRLOK!
- I AM SHOCKED
YOU WOULD ACCUSE ME
OF SUCH AN EVIL ACT.
I ALREADY EXPLAINED.
EQUALISTS ATTACKED US
AND TOOK HER.
- BUT THERE WERE NO CHI-BLOCKERS
HERE LAST NIGHT.
YOU PLANTED THE EVIDENCE,
DIDN'T YOU?
- THAT IS A RIDICULOUS
ACCUSATION!
- IT'S TRUE!
HE TOOK HER!
I WAS HERE WHEN AVATAR KORRA
ARRIVED LAST NIGHT,
BUT COUNCILMAN TARRLOK
ORDERED ME TO LEAVE.
I WAS ON MY WAY OUT
WHEN I SAW TARRLOK
BRING HER DOWN
TO THE GARAGE.
- SAY GOOD-BYE TO REPUBLIC CITY,
AVATAR KORRA.
YOU'LL NEVER SEE IT AGAIN.
- [screams]
- THAT IS NONSENSE.
EVERYONE KNOWS YOU'RE NOTHING
BUT A SQUEAKY-VOICED LIAR.
- WHY DID YOU WAIT UNTIL NOW
TO 'FESS UP?
- I WAS TERRIFIED
TO TELL BECAUSE--
BECAUSE TARRLOK
IS A BLOODBENDER!
HE BLOODBENT AVATAR KORRA!
- DON'T MAKE THIS
WORSE FOR YOURSELF.
TELL US WHERE
YOU HAVE KORRA.
all: [groaning]
[footsteps approach]
- WAKE UP.
- OH!
- OH, MAN.
I HAD THIS AWFUL DREAM
THAT KORRA WAS TAKEN
BY THIS EVIL BLOODBENDER.
SO WEIRD.
- BOLIN, THAT REALLY HAPPENED.
HE KNOCKED US OUT.
- ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WHERE IS HE?
IS HE HERE RIGHT NOW?
- TARRLOK IS LONG GONE.
I'LL ALERT THE WHOLE FORCE.
- WE'VE ONLY BEEN OUT
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
MAYBE WE CAN STILL PICK UP
TARRLOK'S TRAIL.
- IT COULD LEAD US
TO KORRA.
LET'S GO.
- [groaning]
[loud groaning]
- YAKONE, YOU WON'T GET AWAY
WITH THIS.
- [laughs]
REPUBLIC CITY IS MINE,
AVATAR.
I'LL BE BACK ONE DAY
TO CLAIM IT.
- [grunts]
[creature screeches]
[wheel squeaking]
[grunting]
- THIS TIME I'M GONNA
PUT YOU TO SLEEP FOR GOOD.
- [screams]
- [screaming tensely]
- [groans]
- I'M TAKING AWAY YOUR BENDING
FOR GOOD.
- [screams]
- [exhales]
IT'S OVER.
- AANG, THIS WHOLE TIME,
YOU WERE TRYING TO WARN ME
ABOUT TARRLOK.
[door creaks open]
- MY LIFE IS A DISASTER NOW,
THANKS TO YOU.
- SO YOUR LITTLE
BLOODBENDING SECRET'S OUT?
- [growls]
- AND I KNOW HOW YOU BLOODBENT
ME WITHOUT A FULL MOON.
YOU'RE YAKONE'S SON.
- I WAS HIS SON.
BUT IN ORDER TO WIN
REPUBLIC CITY,
I HAD TO BECOME
SOMEONE ELSE.
MY FATHER FAILED BECAUSE
HE TRIED TO RULE THE CITY
FROM ITS ROTTEN UNDERBELLY.
MY PLAN WAS PERFECT.
I WAS TO BE
THE CITY'S SAVIOR.
BUT YOU--
YOU RUINED EVERYTHING!
- TARRLOK, THE JIG IS UP,
AND YOU HAVE NOWHERE
TO GO.
- OH, NO.
NO, I'LL ESCAPE
AND START A NEW LIFE.
AND YOU'RE COMING
AS MY HOSTAGE.
- YOU'LL NEVER GET AWAY
WITH THIS!
[banging]
- AMON.
- [gasps]
- IT IS TIME FOR YOU
TO BE EQUALIZED.
- YOU FOOL.
YOU'VE NEVER FACED BENDING
LIKE MINE.
HUH?
[groans]
WHAT?
WHAT ARE YOU?
- I AM THE SOLUTION.
- [screams]
all: [groaning]
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM.
YOU FOUR RETRIEVE
THE AVATAR.
DO NOT UNDERESTIMATE HER.
ELECTROCUTE THE BOX
TO KNOCK HER OUT
BEFORE YOU OPEN IT.
- MY PLEASURE.
[footsteps approach]
IT'S PAYBACK TIME.
- [screaming]
[glass shatters]
- OPEN THE BOX.
TIE HER UP.
- [screams]
[glass shatters]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
NOT TO UNDERESTIMATE HER.
- OH!
[grunts]
[groans softly]
[Naga panting]
NAGA, YOU CAME LOOKING
FOR ME.
GOOD GIRL.
[creature growls]
[distant howl]
- THAT SOUNDS LIKE NAGA.
DOWN THERE!
- KORRA?
- MM.
- OH, THANK GOODNESS.
- WHERE'S TARRLOK?
HOW DID YOU GET AWAY?
- GIVE HER SOME SPACE.
I WAS SO WORRIED.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I'M FINE.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
- YOU'RE SAFE NOW.