- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- AMON'S REVOLUTION
GROWS STRONGER BY THE DAY.
FIRST, HE ATTACKED
THE BENDING ARENA.
THEN IT WAS DISCOVERED
THAT HIROSHI SATO
WAS THE MASTERMIND
BEHIND THE EQUALIST GLOVES
AND MECHA-TANKS.
AND MOST RECENTLY, AMON AMBUSHED
COUNCILMAN TARRLOK,
TOOK HIS BENDING,
AND NEARLY CAPTURED
THE AVATAR AS WELL.
EVERYONE IS ON EDGE WONDERING,
WHERE WILL AMON STRIKE NEXT?
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- DADDY, YOU'RE HOME.
WE WAITED UP FOR YOU.
IS KORRA OKAY?
- YES, SHE'S FINE,
SWEETIE.
- I WAS SCARED.
I THOUGHT SHE WASN'T
COMING BACK.
- I'M SORRY
YOU WERE SCARED,
BUT EVERYTHING IS GOING
TO BE FINE NOW.
I PROMISE.
- MMM.
MMM.
THE FOOD TASTES
AMAZING, PEMA.
I'M FINALLY STARTING
TO FEEL LIKE MYSELF AGAIN.
- WE'RE SO THANKFUL
YOU'RE HOME SAFE.
- LET ME HELP.
- KORRA, I REALIZE
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH A LOT,
BUT I NEED TO KNOW
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED.
- WELL, FIRST OFF,
TARRLOK ISN'T WHO HE SAYS HE IS.
HE'S YAKONE'S SON.
- IT ALL
MAKES SENSE NOW.
THAT'S HOW TARRLOK WAS ABLE
TO BLOODBEND US
WITHOUT A FULL MOON.
- BUT HOW DID YOU ESCAPE?
AND WHERE'S TARRLOK?
- AMON CAPTURED HIM
AND TOOK HIS BENDING.
- WHAT?
- YEAH.
HE SHOWED UP
OUT OF NOWHERE.
HE ALMOST
GOT ME TOO.
- THIS IS VERY
DISTURBING NEWS.
AMON IS BECOMING
EMBOLDENED.
TAKING OUT A COUNCILMAN,
ALMOST CAPTURING THE AVATAR--
I FEAR AMON IS ENTERING
HIS END GAME.
- [crying out]
- PEMA,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- THE BABY IS JUST KICKING
REALLY HARD, IS ALL.
I'M FINE.
- SHOULD I GET TENZIN?
- NO REASON TO WORRY HIM.
IT'S NOTHING.
- CAN I GET
SOME HOT WATER?
KORRA NEEDS
MORE TEA.
- YOU'RE A FIREBENDER.
BOIL IT YOURSELF.
- I'M GONNA STEP OUT
IN CASE YOU TWO WANT TO TALK.
- IS THERE SOMETHING
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT?
- I'VE NOTICED
HOW YOU TREAT KORRA.
HOW YOU ACTED
WHEN SHE WAS MISSING.
YOU HAVE FEELINGS
FOR HER, DON'T YOU?
- WHAT?
NO.
SHE WAS TAKEN
BY A CRAZY BLOODBENDER.
HOW DID YOU
EXPECT ME TO ACT?
- I LIKE KORRA.
BUT YOU'VE BEEN KEEPING
THE TRUTH FROM ME
THIS WHOLE TIME.
- THE TRUTH?
ABOUT WHAT?
- YOU'RE REALLY
GONNA MAKE ME SAY IT?
- YES, BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
- THE KISS, MAKO.
I KNOW.
- I--WELL...
BOLIN TOLD YOU,
DIDN'T HE?
- DON'T BLAME YOUR BROTHER
FOR WHAT YOU DID.
DO YOU HAVE FEELINGS
FOR KORRA OR NOT?
- LOOK, THINGS ARE CRAZY
RIGHT NOW.
CAN WE DEAL WITH
OUR RELATIONSHIP PROBLEMS LATER?
- WELL, THERE MIGHT NOT
BE ANY RELATIONSHIP
TO WORRY ABOUT LATER.
- ASAMI.
[sighs]
- LIN, UM, I-I NEED
TO ASK YOU A FAVOR.
IT WOULD MEAN
THE WORLD TO ME,
BUT I-I KNOW IT COULD BE
A POTENTIALLY AWKWARD SITUATION.
FURTHERMORE--
- SPIT IT OUT ALREADY.
- WILL YOU STAY HERE AND WATCH
OVER PEMA AND THE CHILDREN
WHILE I MEET
WITH THE COUNCIL?
WITH EVERYTHING
THAT'S HAPPENED LATELY,
I WANT TO BE SURE
MY FAMILY IS IN SAFE HANDS.
- OF COURSE I'LL HELP,
OLD FRIEND.
- I DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU TWO WERE OUT HERE.
- PEMA!
UH, YES, YES.
LIN HAS AGREED
TO HELP OUT AROUND HERE
AND KEEP AN EYE ON THINGS
WHILE I'M AWAY.
- THANK YOU.
I COULD USE
THE EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS.
- [giggling]
- WOULD YOU MIND
GIVING HIM A BATH?
HE'S FILTHY.
- [laughing]
- THIS IS NOT
WHAT I SIGNED ON FOR.
- THANK YOU, LIN.
OOGI, YIP, YIP.
[Oogi growling]
- I GOT TO POO.
REALLY BAD.
OOH! AH!
UGH!
- DO YOU KNOW
WHERE MY KEYS ARE?
I CAN'T FIND
THEM ANYWHERE.
- NO, DEAR.
- OH, FOUND THEM.
- GOOD, DEAR.
- DON'T WAIT UP FOR ME.
THIS COUNCIL SESSION WILL
PROBABLY GO LATE INTO THE NIGHT.
[knocking]
- THE DOOR, DEAR.
- WE'RE HERE TO FIX
A SPIDER-RAT PROBLEM.
- I DIDN'T CALL
AN EXTERMINATOR.
- DEAR?
[growling]
- [grunts]
- UGH!
- AAH!
- OOF!
OH, I'M SO RELIEVED
TO SEE YOU.
- THE OTHER COUNCIL MEMBERS,
ARE THEY ALL RIGHT?
- I'M AFRAID NOT.
I JUST RECEIVED A CALL
FROM CHIEF SAIKHAN.
THEY'VE ALL
BEEN CAPTURED.
- THIS CAN'T BE HAPPENING.
- THE LEADERSHIP
OF REPUBLIC CITY
IS IN YOUR HANDS NOW.
[explosion]
[dramatic music]
IT IS A TRAGIC
DAY INDEED!
- ALL RIGHT, KIDS.
TIME TO GO INSIDE.
- WE HEARD EXPLOSIONS.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- REPUBLIC CITY
IS UNDER ATTACK.
- I'VE DREAMED OF THIS DAY
FOR SO LONG.
- YES.
THE TIME HAS COME
FOR THE EQUALISTS
TO CLAIM REPUBLIC CITY
AS THEIR OWN.
[sirens blaring]
- WHERE DID YOU SAY
YOU PARKED THE CAR?
- IT'S RIGHT
AROUND HERE SOMEWHERE.
THERE IT IS.
- WOW, NICE PARKING JOB.
- HEY, YOU GUYS GOT ARRESTED
AND LEFT ME ALONE WITH THE CAR.
I MADE IT VERY CLEAR
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO DRIVE.
- ALL THINGS CONSIDERED,
YOU DID A GREAT JOB.
BUT HOW ARE WE GONNA PAY
FOR ALL THESE PARKING TICKETS?
[gasps]
- RELAX, THE CITY'S
UNDER ATTACK.
THE POLICE HAVE MORE IMPORTANT
THINGS TO WORRY ABOUT.
- THIS'LL COME IN HANDY.
WHY DON'T YOU SIT IN BACK
WITH KORRA?
- I THINK I WILL.
- EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
- YEAH.
EVERYTHING'S TERRIFIC.
[tires screeching]
- CAR!
OH, WE'RE GOOD.
[sirens blaring]
- CHIEF, AIR UNIT SEVEN
WAS JUST TAKEN OUT
BY AN EQUALIST AIRSHIP.
THEY'VE CRASHED
INTO THE HARBOR.
- SEND A RIVER
RESCUE UNIT.
- CHIEF, ALL RIVER RESCUE SHIPS
HAVE BEEN SABOTAGED.
- WHAT?
- CHIEF SAIKHAN.
- TENZIN, AM I GLAD
TO SEE YOU.
I WAS AFRAID
YOU'D BEEN CAPTURED TOO.
- I'M THE ONLY
COUNCIL MEMBER LEFT.
WHAT'S THE STATUS?
- AMON HAS LAUNCHED
SIMULTANEOUS ATTACKS
ACROSS THE BOROUGHS.
THE POLICE ARE TRYING
TO REGAIN CONTROL,
BUT WE'RE SPREAD
TOO THIN.
- I NEED TO SEND A WIRE.
- TO WHOM, COUNCILMAN?
- THE GENERAL
OF THE UNITED FORCES.
[coughing]
- COUNCILMAN, YOUR WIRE
HAS BEEN SENT.
- CHIEF, THE PHONE LINES
JUST WENT DEAD.
[alarm sounding]
[alarm dying out]
- [gasps]
- CATCH.
- SAIKHAN,
THE VENTS!
[coughing]
WE NEED
TO EVACUATE IMMEDIATELY.
EVERYONE STAY
CLOSE TO ME.
[all gasp]
NOT THESE
MECHA-TANKS AGAIN.
- AAH!
- OOF!
- UGH!
- [grunting]
AAH!
[straining]
- [grunting]
[groans]
SAIKHAN, NO.
[all groaning]
[groans]
- JUMP!
- UGH!
AAH!
- [grunts]
- AAH!
- UGH!
- OH!
[fighting cry]
- [groans]
THANK YOU.
- TENZIN HAS ESCAPED
ONCE AGAIN.
I CAN'T STAND
TO SEE ASAMI FIGHTING
ALONGSIDE THOSE BENDERS.
- WE WILL CAPTURE THEM
BEFORE LONG,
AND YOU WILL HAVE
YOUR DAUGHTER BACK.
- ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I'M FINE.
THANK YOU, KIDS.
ANOTHER MOMENT LATER,
AND I WOULD'VE BEEN
ON MY WAY TO AMON.
- UH, GUYS, LOOK.
- OH, NO.
- EVERYONE, HIDE INSIDE
AND REMAIN CALM.
- AAH!
- PULL IT
TOGETHER, PEMA.
DIDN'T I JUST SAY,
"REMAIN CALM"?
- MOMMY, WHAT'S WRONG?
- THE BABY'S COMING!
- OH, NO.
- NOT NOW, BABY!
- [moaning]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
- THE CHILDREN,
WHERE ARE THEY?
- DON'T WORRY.
THEY'RE IN THE OTHER ROOM,
TOTALLY SAFE.
- AAH!
[groans]
- STAY AWAY FROM MY DAD'S
EX-GIRLFRIEND.
- UGH! OOF!
- JINORA!
YOU SHOULDN'T
BE OUT HERE!
[grunting]
- GET OFF OUR ISLAND!
- GIRLS, YOU NEED TO GO
BACK INSIDE THIS INSTANT.
- TASTE MY FURY!
[farts]
- MEELO, BE CAREFUL!
- [fighting grunts]
[farts]
[roaring]
- NEVER MIND.
TAKE THESE EQUALISTS
AND LOCK THEM
IN THE TEMPLE'S BASEMENT.
NICE WORK, KIDS.
[growling]
- DAD!
- OH, THANK GOODNESS
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
- WE CAUGHT
THE BAD GUYS.
- YOU LET THEM FIGHT?
DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT COULD'VE HAPPENED?
- I WOULD'VE BEEN TOAST
IF IT WEREN'T FOR YOUR KIDS.
YOU SHOULD BE PROUD.
YOU TAUGHT THEM WELL.
GO ON.
BE WITH YOUR WIFE.
[baby wailing]
- PEMA!
[baby cries]
- TENZIN.
- I'M HERE, PEMA.
- OUR NEW SON.
- [cooing]
- HELLO.
COME, MEET
YOUR NEW BROTHER.
- A BROTHER?
WELL, IT'S ABOUT TIME.
- WELCOME.
I'M IKKI, AND THIS IS JINORA
AND MEELO.
WE HAVE A SUPER
GREAT FAMILY,
AND WE'RE SO HAPPY
THAT YOU'RE A PART OF IT.
- WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA NAME HIM?
CAN I PICK?
- WE ALREADY CHOSE
A NAME.
- ROHAN.
- I'M SO SORRY
TO INTERRUPT, BUT...
MORE AIRSHIPS
ARE COMING.
- EVERYTHING'S NOT
GONNA BE FINE,
IS IT, DADDY?
- [whimpering]
- WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO DO, TENZIN?
- [sighs]
I NEED TO PROTECT
MY FAMILY
AND GET THEM AS FAR AWAY
FROM THIS CONFLICT AS POSSIBLE.
IF AMON GOT HIS HANDS
ON MY CHILDREN--
I HATE TO EVEN
THINK OF IT.
- IF YOU'RE LEAVING,
THEN I'M GOING WITH YOU.
- BUT--
- NO ARGUMENTS.
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY
ARE THE LAST AIRBENDERS.
THERE'S NO WAY
IN THE WORLD
I'M LETTING AMON
TAKE YOUR BENDING AWAY.
- THANK YOU, LIN.
KORRA, I WANT YOU
TO LEAVE THIS ISLAND
AND HIDE
FOR THE TIME BEING.
- I'M NOT GIVING UP.
- I'M NOT ASKING YOU TO.
I'VE SENT WORD
TO THE UNITED FORCES.
THEY WILL BE HERE SOON.
AND ONCE MY FAMILY IS SAFE,
I WILL RETURN.
WITH THE REINFORCEMENTS, WE CAN
TURN THE TIDE IN THIS WAR.
- WHAT YOU'RE SAYING IS
WE NEED TO BE PATIENT.
- YOU'RE LEARNING WELL.
STAY SAFE, KORRA.
- YOU TOO.
- TENZIN, IF WE'RE LEAVING,
WE'D BETTER DO IT NOW.
- OOGI, YIP, YIP.
[Oogi growling]
[growls]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- GO.
WE'LL HOLD THEM OFF.
- EVERYONE, CLIMB ON.
LET'S GO, GIRL.
- MOUSTACHE GUY!
[growling]
- AAH!
- NICE ONE, NAGA.
[growls]
- THEY'RE GAINING
ON US!
- FASTER, OOGI!
[Oogi growls]
- WHATEVER HAPPENS TO ME,
DON'T TURN BACK.
- LIN, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
- [grunts]
OOF!
UGH! AAH!
- THAT LADY
IS MY HERO.
- YES, SHE IS.
[growling]
[growls]
- KORRA,
WE SHOULD GET MOVING.
- UGH!
- TELL ME WHERE
THE AVATAR IS,
AND I'LL LET YOU
KEEP YOUR BENDING.
- I WON'T TELL YOU ANYTHING,
YOU MONSTER.
- VERY WELL.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- GENERAL, I JUST RECEIVED
A WIRE FROM THE AVATAR.
SHE SAYS AMON AND HIS FORCES
HAVE GAINED CONTROL OF THE CITY.
HOW DO YOU WANT
TO RESPOND?
- TELL HER WE WILL BE ARRIVING
IN THREE DAYS TIME
AND THAT I LOOK FORWARD
TO WINNING BACK REPUBLIC CITY.
TOGETHER.
- AS YOU WISH,
GENERAL IROH.