- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- THE EQUALISTS
ARE ON THE ATTACK.
THE LIEUTENANT
AND HIS CHI-BLOCKERS
INVADED AIR TEMPLE ISLAND
AND FORCED TENZIN
AND HIS FAMILY TO FLEE.
IN THE DARING ESCAPE,
LIN BEIFONG SACRIFICED HERSELF
AND SAVED THE AIRBENDERS.
BUT SHE WAS CAPTURED,
AND AMON TOOK HER BENDING AWAY.
NOW TEAM AVATAR IS IN HIDING
AS THEY AWAIT HELP
FROM GENERAL IROH
AND THE UNITED FORCES.
- IT IS A GLORIOUS DAY,
MY EQUALIST BROTHERS
AND SISTERS.
AMON HAS TORN DOWN THE
TYRANNICAL BENDING GOVERNMENT!
HE HAS DECLARED
BENDING ILLEGAL.
AND HE HAS THE AVATAR
ON THE RUN.
OUR GREAT LEADER HAS A VISION
FOR THE FUTURE.
ONE DAY SOON,
BENDING WILL NO LONGER EXIST
AND WE WILL LIVE IN A WORLD
WHERE EVERYONE IS FINALLY EQUAL!
THE UNITED FORCES
ARE ON THEIR WAY RIGHT NOW
TO TRY AND STOP THAT DREAM.
BUT WE WILL PREVAIL!
[cheers and applause]
- CAN YOU BELIEVE HIROSHI?
"THE AVATAR'S ON THE RUN."
I'M NOT RUNNING FROM ANYONE.
LET'S GO BACK UP THERE
AND KNOCK SOME HEADS. THEY'LL
NEVER KNOW WHAT HIT THEM.
- RELAX.
GENERAL IROH'S COMING
WITH AN ENTIRE FLEET
OF BATTLESHIPS.
THEN AMON WILL BE
THE ONE WHO'S RUNNING.
- I HATE THIS
"BEING PATIENT" STUFF.
- [squeaking]
- YOU TWO WERE GONE A WHILE.
- WE WERE DOING RECONNAISSANCE.
- WHATEVER.
- WELCOME BACK!
HOPE YOU WORKED UP AN APPETITE,
'CAUSE DINNER IS SERVED.
- THANKS SO MUCH FOR
LETTING US HIDE OUT WITH YOU
THE PAST FEW DAYS.
- HONORED TO OBLIGE.
MY ASSOCIATES AND I
HARDLY OPPOSE AMON'S SO-CALLED
"EQUALIST" POLICIES.
WE GOT BENDERS AND NON-BENDERS
LIVING TOGETHER DOWN HERE.
BUT DO YOU SEE US FIGHTING?
NO, SIR-REE.
WE'VE FIGURED OUT HOW
TO HARMONIOUSLY CO-EXIST.
- YOU ARE A WISE
AND NOBLE HOBO.
MMM.
THIS IS THE BEST
TASTING STREET GRUEL
I'VE EVER HAD.
SERIOUSLY.
- I CULLED IT FROM
THE FINEST DUMPSTERS
THE CITY HAS TO OFFER.
- [chokes]
BLAGH!
[coughing]
- [squeaking]
- CAN'T SLEEP EITHER?
- NO, I HAVE THIS
AWFUL PIT IN MY STOMACH.
- ME TOO.
- IT'S SO CRAZY.
A FEW MONTHS AGO
I WAS IN THE SOUTH POLE,
PRACTICING FOR
MY FIRE BENDING TEST.
AND NOW I'M IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN ALL-OUT WAR.
- I KNOW. WE DIDN'T
EVEN KNOW EACH OTHER THEN.
AND NOW, I CAN'T IMAGINE
MY LIFE WITHOUT YOU IN IT.
YOU'RE THE MOST LOYAL,
BRAVE, AND SELFLESS PERSON
I'VE EVER KNOWN.
- I THINK YOU'RE
PRETTY INCREDIBLE TOO,
BUT YOU ALREADY KNEW THAT.
I SHOULD PROBABLY
TRY TO GET SOME SLEEP.
- ME TOO.
GOOD NIGHT.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- [groans]
- YOU WILL NOW BE CLEANSED
OF YOUR IMPURITY.
- [groans]
- NEXT.
- [whimpers]
- COAST IS CLEAR.
- ONCE THE UNITED FORCES ARRIVE,
WE NEED TO BE READY TO HELP
IN ANY WAY WE CAN.
- THEY'RE HERE.
- [gasps]
WHOOPS.
- HMM.
AMON HAD TO KNOW
WE WERE COMING.
SO WHY AREN'T
WE MEETING ANY RESISTANCE?
- WAIT A SECOND.
WHERE ARE THE EQUALIST AIRSHIPS?
I DON'T SEE ANY
MECHA-TANKS EITHER.
- SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT.
[boom]
IT'S A TRICK!
WATER AND EARTHBENDERS,
DETONATE THOSE MINES!
[muffled explosions]
WHAT IS THAT SOUND?
[low buzzing]
[buzzing increases]
- WHAT NOW?
[engines rumbling]
- WHERE DOES HIROSHI
FIND THE TIME
TO KEEP INVENTING
NEW EVIL MACHINES?
[whistling]
- INCOMING!
[screaming]
- [gasps]
- HUNH!
[screams]
- [deep breath]
- AAAAH!
- [gasps]
[water bubbling]
- [gasps, coughs]
- IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'VE GOT YOU.
- [coughing]
AVATAR KORRA...
YOU SAVED MY LIFE.
THANK YOU.
I WAS PREPARED TO DEAL
WITH SATO'S MECHA-TANKS,
BUT NOT THESE NEW
HIGH-SPEED AIRCRAFT.
- I KNOW.
EVERY TIME WE THINK
WE HAVE AN ADVANTAGE,
AMON OUTSMARTS US.
- NO MATTER WHAT OUR PLAN IS,
HE ALWAYS HAS A BETTER ONE.
- AMON IS WINNING SO FAR,
BUT WE'RE NOT
OUT OF THE FIGHT YET.
- I LIKE THIS MAN'S CONFIDENCE.
SO HOW ARE WE NOT
OUT OF THE FIGHT?
- A SECOND WAVE
OF REINFORCEMENTS
IS ON THE WAY.
BUT I NEED TO WARN THEM.
DO YOU STILL HAVE A WAY
TO GET A MESSAGE OUT?
- I KNOW JUST THE MAN
FOR THE JOB.
[click]
- AND WHO IS
THE RECIPIENT
OF THIS TOP-SECRET MESSAGE?
- COMMANDER BUMI.
SECOND DIVISION
OF THE UNITED FORCES.
[knuckles cracking]
- TENZIN'S BROTHER?
- YES.
A BIT OF A WILD MAN.
BUT THE BRAVEST COMMANDER
YOU'LL EVER MEET.
- READY, SIR!
- FLEET AMBUSHED AND DESTROYED
BY EQUALIST AIRCRAFT.
RETREAT TO RED SAND ISLAND
UNTIL MY SIGNAL.
DO NOT APPROACH CITY
UNTIL YOU RECEIVE THE ALL-CLEAR.
[beeping]
NOW COMES THE HARD PART.
WE NEED TO GROUND
THOSE AIRCRAFT,
OTHERWISE BUMI'S FLEET
WILL NEVER BE ABLE
TO RETAKE THE CITY.
- THEY FLEW IN
FROM THIS DIRECTION.
THE AIRFIELD MUST BE SOMEWHERE
OVER THIS MOUNTAIN RANGE.
- EVERYONE GET READY.
WE LEAVE AT DAWN.
- IT'S TIME
TO TAKE DOWN MY FATHER.
- WAIT.
I'M SORRY, BUT I'M NOT
GOING WITH YOU TOMORROW.
- WHAT?
- WHY NOT?
- I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF HIDING FROM AMON.
IT'S TIME I FACE HIM.
- THAT'S NOT A GOOD PLAN.
WE NEED TO STICK TOGETHER.
- I'M NOT WAITING FOR HIM
TO HUNT ME DOWN.
MY GUT'S TELLING ME
IT'S TIME TO END THIS.
ON MY TERMS.
- KORRA, THIS IS NOT A MISSION
YOU SHOULD BE HANDLING ALONE.
- SHE WON'T BE.
I'M GOING WITH YOU.
- YOU DON'T
HAVE TO DO THAT.
- YES, I DO.
- [sighs]
MY GRANDFATHER WOULD
RESPECT THE AVATAR'S INSTINCT.
SO WILL I.
- LOVE YOU, LITTLE BRO.
- LOVE YOU BACK, BIG BRO.
- [sniffling]
- KORRA, AMON IS A NASTY DUDE.
BE CAREFUL.
- I WILL.
GOOD LUCK.
IF YOU'RE GOING
INTO THE MOUNTAINS,
YOU SHOULD BRING NAGA.
- [grunts]
- TAKE GOOD CARE OF BOLIN
FOR ME.
- ASAMI.
I'M SORRY THINGS GOT
SO MESSED UP BETWEEN US.
BUT WHATEVER HAPPENS TODAY,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
HOW MUCH
I CARE ABOUT YOU.
- I CARE ABOUT YOU TOO.
- GOOD FORTUNE AND SUCCESS
TO YOU, VALIANT HEROES.
- THERE'S AMON!
- WE NEED TO GET
INTO THE TEMPLE.
THEN, WHEN HE RETURNS...
- WE AMBUSH HIM.
- WHAT ARE YOU
TWO DOING HERE?
- UH,
WE WERE JUST TRANSFERRED.
- WELL, YOU'RE GETTING
TRANSFERRED AGAIN.
AMON WANTS EXTRA SECURITY
AT THE ARENA TODAY.
- THE ARENA? FOR WHAT?
- THE RALLY.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
BEEN BRIEFED ABOUT THIS.
- WE'LL BE THERE, SIR!
I KNOW ANOTHER WAY IN.
LET'S HIDE IN THE ATTIC.
- UH, WE'RE NOT ALONE UP HERE.
- TARRLOK?
- I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU'RE HERE TO RESCUE ME?
- WE HAD NO IDEA
YOU WERE HERE.
ARE THERE OTHER PRISONERS
ON THE ISLAND?
- NO, I'M THE ONLY ONE.
- AND WHAT MAKES YOU
SO SPECIAL?
- I'M AMON'S BROTHER.
both: [gasp]
- AMON IS FROM
THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE.
HE IS A WATERBENDER AND
A BLOODBENDER, JUST LIKE I WAS.
- WHAT?!
- DID YOU KNOW
THIS ALL ALONG?
- NO, NOT UNTIL
AFTER HE CAPTURED ME.
- HOW DID YOUR BROTHER
END UP BECOMING AMON?
- IT ALL BEGAN
WITH MY FATHER, YAKONE...
WITH THE HELP
OF HIS FORMER GANG,
HE ESCAPED PRISON
AND UNDERWENT SURGERY
TO CHANGE HIS APPEARANCE.
HE ASSUMED A NEW IDENTITY
AND SETTLED DOWN
IN THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE.
THAT'S WHERE HE MET MY MOTHER.
A WARM, CARING WOMAN.
BEFORE LONG, THEY STARTED
A FAMILY TOGETHER.
- [laughs]
- AMON WAS THE FIRSTBORN,
UNDER THE NAME NOATAK.
I WAS BORN
THREE YEARS LATER...
NOATAK WAS A GOOD-NATURED KID,
ALWAYS LOOKING OUT FOR ME.
THOSE WERE THE GOOD YEARS,
BEFORE MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED WE WERE WATERBENDERS.
AT FIRST WE WERE EXCITED
BY OUR NEW ABILITIES,
BUT OUR TRAINING BROUGHT OUT
A DIFFERENT SIDE OF MY FATHER.
- TARRLOK,
YOU BETTER SHAPE UP
OR YOU'LL BE OUT HERE
IN THE COLD ALL NIGHT
UNTIL YOU GET IT RIGHT.
- I'M TRYING, BUT--
- TRY HARDER!
YOUR BROTHER
WAS NEVER THIS SLOPPY.
- DAD, HE'LL GET IT.
HE JUST NEEDS TIME.
- DON'T TALK BACK TO ME, SON.
EVER!
- EVEN BACK THEN,
MY BROTHER WANTED EVERYONE
TO BE TREATED
FAIRLY AND EQUALLY.
WHEN I WAS SEVEN,
MY FATHER TOOK ME AND NOATAK
ON A HUNTING TRIP,
FAR AWAY FROM OUR HOME.
HE TOLD US HIS TRUE IDENTITY
WAS YAKONE,
REPUBLIC CITY'S
MOST NOTORIOUS CRIME BOSS.
AND THAT HE WAS ONCE
A BLOODBENDER OF RARE SKILL.
- WHAT'S BLOODBENDING?
- THE MOST POWERFUL AND FEARED
FORM OF BENDING IN THE WORLD.
IT WAS DECLARED ILLEGAL,
THANKS TO THAT COWARD KATARA.
OUR FAMILY HAS THE STRONGEST
LINE OF BLOODBENDERS IN HISTORY.
YOU BOYS HAVE THIS POWER
INSIDE OF YOU.
AND I WILL TEACH YOU
TO MASTER IT.
- WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR BENDING, DAD?
- THE AVATAR
STOLE IT FROM ME.
THAT'S WHY I BROUGHT YOU
OUT HERE--TO LEARN YOUR DESTINY.
YOU TWO WILL BECOME BLOODBENDERS
OF THE HIGHEST ORDER.
WHEN THE TIME IS RIGHT,
YOU WILL CLAIM REPUBLIC CITY--
AND YOU WILL
DESTROY THE AVATAR.
YOU MUST AVENGE ME.
THAT IS YOUR PURPOSE IN LIFE.
- THE GOOD DAYS
WERE BEHIND US.
EVERY FULL MOON,
OUR FATHER TOOK US ON
ANOTHER SUPPOSED "HUNTING" TRIP,
WHERE HE SECRETLY TRAINED US
IN BLOODBENDING.
WE KEPT THE TRUTH
FROM OUR MOTHER.
[animal groans]
[groaning]
- STOP! YOU'RE HURTING IT!
- TOUGHEN UP, TARRLOK.
YOU'LL NEED
A THICKER SKIN FOR THIS.
[animal groans]
VERY GOOD, SON.
VERY GOOD.
- A FEW YEARS LATER,
MY FATHER TAUGHT US
TO BLOODBEND ANYTIME,
WITHOUT THE NEED
OF THE FULL MOON.
WE PRACTICED CONSTANTLY,
AND I HATED
EVERY MINUTE OF IT.
[growling, barking]
[whining]
I HAD NO STOMACH FOR
MANIPULATING HELPLESS ANIMALS.
MY BROTHER, HOWEVER, SEEMED
TO REVEL IN HIS NEWFOUND POWER.
- [inhales]
[whining]
- HE WAS A PRODIGY,
MASTERING MY FATHER'S
PSYCHIC BLOODBENDING TECHNIQUE
BY THE TIME HE WAS 14.
[whining]
- [gasps]
- THAT'S THE WAY IT'S DONE.
THAT'S WHAT YOU NEED
TO STRIVE FOR.
- EVEN THOUGH NOATAK
WAS MY FATHER'S FAVORITE,
IT WASN'T ANY EASIER
FOR HIM.
HE CARRIED THE BURDEN
OF ALL YAKONE'S
EXPECTATIONS AND DEMANDS.
SOMETHING CHANGED
IN NOATAK OVER THE YEARS.
THE LOVING BROTHER I ONCE KNEW
BECAME COLD AND DETACHED.
[thunder rumbling]
OUR FATHER PUSHED US
TO EXTREMES.
AND ONE DAY, HE MADE US
BLOODBEND EACH OTHER.
- NOATAK, GO.
- [inhales]
- [groans]
[screams]
- EXCELLENT.
- UHH!
[panting]
- TARRLOK!
YOUR TURN.
- NO, I WON'T DO IT.
- BLOODBEND YOUR BROTHER,
TARRLOK!
- THAT FELT AWFUL!
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THAT TO ANYONE!
I NEVER WANT TO
BLOODBEND AGAIN!
- YOU'RE A DISGRACE,
A WEAKLING.
I'LL TEACH YOU A LESSON,
YOU INSUBORDINATE--
UNH!
- STAY AWAY FROM HIM.
- HOW DARE YOU BLOODBEND ME!
- WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO ABOUT IT?
YOU'RE THE WEAK ONE.
- UNH! AAH!
- YOU ALWAYS SAY BLOODBENDING
IS THE MOST POWERFUL THING
IN THE WORLD, BUT IT ISN'T--
THE AVATAR IS.
HE TOOK YOUR BENDING AWAY.
WHAT COULD BE MORE
POWERFUL THAN THAT?
- I MADE YOU WHAT YOU ARE!
YOU'RE MINE!
- WE'RE YOUR SONS,
NOT YOUR TOOLS OF REVENGE!
LET'S GO.
WE CAN RUN AWAY
FROM HIM, FOREVER.
- RUN AWAY?
BUT WHAT ABOUT MOM?
WE CAN'T JUST LEAVE HER.
- HE WAS RIGHT ABOUT YOU.
YOU ARE A WEAKLING.
HUNH!
- AAH!
- NOATAK! DON'T LEAVE, PLEASE!
NOATAK!
MY FATHER AND I SEARCHED
FOR DAYS,
BUT WE NEVER FOUND
A SIGN OF NOATAK.
WE THOUGHT HE PERISHED
IN THAT STORM.
MY MOTHER WAS NEVER THE SAME
AFTER THE LOSS OF MY BROTHER.
MY FATHER STOPPED TRAINING ME.
WITH NOATAK GONE,
HIS HOPES FOR REVENGE WITHERED,
AND HE PASSED AWAY
A FEW YEARS LATER.
- THAT'S ONE OF THE SADDEST
STORIES I'VE EVER HEARD.
- AVATAR KORRA,
I AM TRULY SORRY
FOR ALL THAT
I DID TO YOU.
I THOUGHT I WAS BETTER
THAN MY FATHER,
BUT HIS GHOST
STILL SHAPED ME.
I BECAME A SOLDIER
OF REVENGE,
JUST LIKE HE WANTED ME
TO BE.
AND SO DID MY BROTHER.
THE REVOLUTION
MAY BE BUILT ON A LIE,
BUT I THINK AMON TRULY BELIEVES
BENDING IS THE SOURCE
OF ALL EVIL IN THE WORLD.
- HOW DID YOU FIGURE OUT
AMON IS YOUR BROTHER?
- WHEN HE TOOK MY BENDING,
THE SENSATION
WAS SOMEHOW FAMILIAR.
I LATER RECOGNIZED IT AS MY
BROTHER'S BLOODBENDING GRIP.
- SO HE SOMEHOW
USES BLOODBENDING
TO TAKE PEOPLE'S BENDING?
- I DON'T KNOW HOW
HE DOES IT, BUT THEN AGAIN,
I'VE NEVER ENCOUNTERED A BENDER
AS STRONG AS NOATAK.
- HOW IN THE WORLD
DO WE BEAT HIM?
- WE CAN'T.
ANY ATTACK WE THROW AT HIM
HE'LL REDIRECT WITH HIS MIND.
THAT'S HOW HE'S BEEN ABLE
TO CHALLENGE ANY BENDER.
- SO MUCH FOR OUR AMBUSH.
IF WE STAY HERE, WE'RE TOAST.
BUT THERE'S ANOTHER WAY
TO BEAT HIM.
- HOW?
- THIS WHOLE TIME,
AMON HAS BEEN
ONE STEP AHEAD OF US.
BUT FINALLY WE HAVE
THE ADVANTAGE--
WE KNOW THE TRUTH ABOUT HIM.
IF WE EXPOSE HIM
AS A BENDER
IN FRONT OF ALL
HIS SUPPORTERS...
- AT THE RALLY...
- WE COULD TAKE AWAY
HIS TRUE POWER.
AND UNDERMINE
THIS WHOLE REVOLUTION!
- THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
WE CAN'T JUST
LEAVE HIM HERE.
- GO. AMON CAN'T KNOW
ANYONE SPOKE WITH ME.
DEFEAT HIM.
PUT AN END TO THIS SAD STORY.