Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring baIance to the world.
Korra and Mako have discovered
the truth about Amon's identity.
He's a Waterbender, a Bloodbender
and brother to Tarrlok.
Now, Korra and Mako pIan
to infiItrate the EquaIist victory raIIy
and expose Amon as a fraud.
Meanwhile,
Asami, Bolin and General lroh
head towards Hiroshi's secret airfield,
where Asami
intends to take down her father.
l think we found our secret airfield.
Bolin, once we get down there,
l need you to tear up those runways.
-We can't let those aircraft take off.
-Aye-aye, Captain.
General. General.
All right, you guys wait here
until we get back, okay?
Stay.
Why would there be fence posts
but no fence?
Thank you all
forjoining me on this historic occasion.
When l was a boy,
a Firebender struck down
my entire family and left me scarred.
That tragic event
began my quest to equalize the world.
That's a lie, Amon.
Or should l call you Noatak?
-You want her taken out?
-No.
Everyone, calm down.
We have nothing to fear
from the Avatar.
Let's hear what she has to say.
Amon has been lying to you.
The Spirits didn't give him the power
to take people's bending away.
He uses bloodbending to do it.
Amon is a Waterbender.
What is this nonsense?
You're desperate, Avatar.
Making up stories about me
is a pathetic last resort.
Your family
wasn't killed by a Firebender.
His father was Yakone,
and his brother is Councilman Tarrlok.
An amusing tale.
But l will show you the truth.
This is what a Firebender did to me.
What?
The Avatar is lying.
l'm telling you, he's a Waterbender.
They don't believe me. lt didn't work.
We said what we had to.
Let's get out of here.
l wouldn't leave yet, Avatar.
You'll miss the main event.
No. They got away.
We saw them get away.
Asami.
Asami, l know l have hurt you,
and l am sorry.
But l believe that one day,
you will come to your senses
and we can be a family again.
Are you insane?
How can we be a family
after everything you've done?
Mom would hate you
for what you've become.
How dare you! l am avenging her death!
-The airplanes are ready for takeoff, sir.
-Good. Annihilate the fleet.
That's right, General.
l intercepted
your message to Commander Bumi.
l know exactly where they're hiding.
How are we going to get out of here?
l don't suppose
you know how to metalbend?
That is a negative, sir.
Naga, over here.
Who needs a Metalbender?
We got Naga. Yeah!
-l'm going after those airplanes.
-No! No, Naga!
What do you know?
Just like a Future lndustries forklift.
Tonight, l rid the world of airbending.
Forever.
Amon, let them go.
You're welcome to
come down here and try to stop me.
-He's trying to bait you.
-l don't care. We have to save them.
The Avatar needs to be reminded of
the power l possess.
-Where are Pema and the baby?
-ln prison.
-Beifong?
-l don't know.
Follow me, kids.
Get them out of here.
We'll create a diversion.
-Let's go get your mother and the baby.
-Prison break!
Let her go!
No!
Korra!
l told you l would destroy you.
Thanks for looking out for me, Aang.
Thanks, Naga.
Asami.
What do you think you're doing?
You are aiding the very people
who took your mother away.
You don't feel love for Mom anymore.
You're too full of hatred.
You ungratefuI, insoIent chiId!
l now see
there is no chance to save you.
Mr. Sato, you are a horrible father.
You really are a horrible father.
Finally, you are powerless.
Amon.
Everything the Avatar said is true,
isn't it?
l just saw you bloodbend her.
You traitor. l dedicated my life to you.
You served me well, Lieutenant.
Mako. My bending...
Everything will be all right.
We just need to get out of here.
l'm impressed.
No one has ever
gotten the better of me like that.
lt is almost a shame to take the bending
of someone so talented.
Almost.
No!
lmpossible!
l... l can airbend?
l can airbend!
No, you don't!
Did you see what happened?
Who was that?
Could that be...
-You bending tyrant.
-Evil Avatar.
What did you do to our leader?
-He's waterbending!
-What?
-He is a bender.
-The scar is fake.
The Avatar was telling the truth.
Noatak.
lt's over, brother.
l'm sorry for what l had to do to you.
Our father set us on this path.
Fate caused us to collide.
l should have left with you
when we were boys.
Leave with me now.
We have a second chance.
We can start over together.
Please.
You're all l have left in the world.
l can't believe Amon got you, too.
Hey, at least
you unlocked your airbending.
Bro, not the time.
Right. Right. l'll just stand over here.
Quietly. ln silence.
-You saved Republic City.
-But Amon got away.
Uncle Bumi's here!
Great.
Now l have to entertain my brother.
The two of us together again,
there's nothing we can't do.
Yes, Noatak.
"Noatak."
l had almost forgotten
the sound of my own name.
lt will be just like the good old days.
l've tried everything in my power,
but l cannot restore Korra's bending.
But you're the best healer in the world.
You have to keep trying.
l'm sorry, there's nothing else l can do.
Korra can still airbend,
but her connection to the other elements
has been severed.
lt's going to be all right, Korra.
No, it's not.
Korra, wait.
Go away.
l will, but l just want you to know
l'm here for you.
No, l mean go away,
back to Republic City.
Get on with your life.
What are you talking about?
l'm not the Avatar anymore.
You don't need to do me any favors.
l don't care if you're the Avatar or not.
Listen, when Tarrlok took you,
l was losing my mind at the thought of
never seeing you again.
l realized l love you, Korra.
l...
-l can't.
-Korra!
We need to be patient with her.
lt will take time for her to accept
what has happened.
Not now, Tenzin.
l just want to be left alone.
But you called me here.
Aang.
You have finally connected
with your spiritual self.
How?
When we hit our lowest point,
we are open to the greatest change.
l love you, too.
Thank you.
l am so proud of you, Avatar Korra.