- EARTH,
FIRE,
AIR,
WATER...
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- SIX MONTHS AGO,
AVATAR KORRA DEFEATED
AMON AND THE EQUALISTS.
SINCE THEN,
THE COUNCIL WAS DISBANDED
AND THE UNITED REPUBLIC
ELECTED ITS FIRST PRESIDENT.
TENZIN'S BROTHER,
COMMANDER BUMI,
RETIRED AND MOVED
TO AIR TEMPLE ISLAND.
AND KORRA
AND HER BOYFRIEND, MAKO,
HAVE BEEN THE TALK
OF THE TOWN.
PEACE HAS COME
TO REPUBLIC CITY,
BUT UNBEKNOWNST
TO THE AVATAR,
DANGER NOW THREATENS
THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE.
[horn blares]
- THIS YOUR FIRST WATCH?
- MM-HMM.
- WELL THEN,
YOU'D BETTER KEEP
YOUR EYES PEELED,
LADDIE.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT CREATURES
LURK IN THE MURKY DEPTHS.
- [gasps]
[thunder rumbling]
- [chuckling]
- UH, SIR.
- WHAT?
AAH!
- MAN OVERBOARD!
MAN OVERBOARD!
[bell dings]
- IT'S PRO-BENDING NIGHT
IN REPUBLIC CITY,
AND HAVE WE GOT A DOOZY
FOR YOU.
FAN FAVORITES,
THE FIRE FERRETS,
ARE ABOUT TO TAKE ON
HOT NEWCOMERS,
THE RHINO-LIONS.
- NOW WE ALL KNOW THAT
OUR LAST MATCH WAS GARBAGE.
TERRIBLE.
EVEN PABU COULD HAVE DONE
A BETTER JOB.
[Pabu chitters]
BUT THAT'S IN THE PAST,
BECAUSE WHEN YOU BACK
A FIRE FERRET IN THE CORNER,
WELL, MISTER,
HE COMES OUT FIGHTING!
[Pabu hisses]
SO LET'S GET OUT THERE
AND BEND LIKE
THERE'S NO TOMORROW.
ARE YOU WITH ME?
- [sniffs]
[bell dings]
[all grunt]
[buzzer]
- OOH, THE FIRE FERRETS
GO DOWN IN THE WATER
AND RIGHT INTO
THE RECORD BOOKS
FOR THE FASTEST KNOCKOUT
IN PRO-BENDING HISTORY.
- WHERE'S MAKO
WHEN I NEED HIM?
[sirens wail,
motorcycle revs]
[tires squeal]
[sirens wail]
[motorcycle revs]
- [gasps]
[truck honks]
[tires screech]
[explosion]
[tires screeching]
[men groan]
LOOKS LIKE YOU
HAD SOME CAR TROUBLE.
GOOD THING THE POLICE
ARE HERE.
- I THINK THESE PLANES
ARE FINALLY READY TO SHIP.
- I HATE TO MENTION
THE ELEPHANT-RHINO IN THE ROOM,
BUT SINCE YOUR FATHER
WAS THROWN IN PRISON,
NO COMPANY
WILL WORK WITH US.
WE'RE NEARLY BANKRUPT.
- DON'T WORRY.
I'M GOING TO
THE SOUTH POLE
TO MEET WITH SOMEONE
WHO CAN HELP US
PUT FUTURE INDUSTRIES
BACK ON TOP.
[Oogi grumbles]
- WAH!
- [coughs]
THE AVATAR IS THE WINNER!
- NO FAIR.
YOU CAN'T GO INTO
THE AVATAR STATE TO WIN.
- [raspberries]
- YOU DID WHAT?
THE AVATAR STATE IS NOT
TO BE USED AS A BOOSTER ROCKET.
YOU ARE TOYING WITH
A DANGEROUS POWER
THAT YOU OBVIOUSLY
DO NOT APPRECIATE.
- IT'S THE "AVATAR STATE,"
AND I'M THE AVATAR.
WHO APPRECIATES IT
MORE THAN ME?
- CLEARLY, YOU NEED
MORE TRAINING TO GRASP
THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SPIRITUAL CONNECTIONS,
NOT TO MENTION THAT
YOU'RE STILL A LONG WAY
FROM MASTERING
AIRBENDING.
- I HAVE MASTERED
PUNCH, PUNCH, PUNCH!
SEE? MASTERED.
- LOOKS PRETTY GOOD TO ME.
- [sighs]
IS IT TOO LATE FOR YOU
TO UN-RETIRE
FROM THE UNITED FORCES?
- THE PAPERWORK'S GONE THROUGH,
LITTLE BROTHER.
FROM NOW ON,
IT'S 24/7 BUMI TIME!
- YOU'VE MASTERED
KORRA-STYLE AIRBENDING.
NOW YOU NEED TO MASTER
REAL AIRBENDING.
HOPEFULLY, OUR VISIT
TO ALL OF THE AIR TEMPLES
WILL GIVE YOU
THE INSPIRATION YOU NEED
TO DELVE MORE DEEPLY
INTO YOUR STUDIES.
- CAN WE SEE WHERE
GRANDPA AANG WAS BORN?
- HOW MANY LEMURS
CAN I HAVE?
- I WANT TO GET TATTOOS,
BUT INSTEAD OF ARROWS
I WANT LIGHTNING BOLTS.
- YOU CAN'T
GET LIGHTNING BOLTS.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
- YOU DON'T MAKE ANY SENSE!
- FIGHT, FIGHT, FIGHT!
[both grumbling]
- NO ONE'S FIGHTING.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
A WONDERFUL TIME.
[groans]
NOW THAT THE PRESIDENT
IS IN OFFICE
AND I'M NOT NEEDED
ON THE COUNCIL,
I CAN FINALLY RELAX
WITH MY FAMILY
AND GIVE KORRA
THE ATTENTION SHE NEEDS.
- GREAT.
MORE ATTENTION.
- [laughs]
RELAX?
I'D PAY MONEY TO SEE THAT.
MAYBE I'LL TAG ALONG
JUST TO SEE "VACATION TENZIN."
- YOU'RE NOT INVITED.
- BEFORE WE GO ON
YOUR DAD'S STUDY TRIP,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
SOME REAL FUN IN MY HOMETOWN
AT THE GLACIER SPIRITS
FESTIVAL.
THEY'VE GOT RIDES, GAMES,
AND ALL KINDS
OF FRIED FOOD ON STICKS.
all: YAY!
[excitedly chattering]
- YEP,
THERE'S VACATION TENZIN.
AND YOU CAN'T STOP ME
FROM GOING TO THE FESTIVAL.
MOM ALREADY INVITED ME.
[horn blares]
- [chuckles]
SO I WALK UP AND SAY,
"LOOKS LIKE YOU
HAD SOME CAR TROUBLE.
GOOD THING
THE POLICE ARE HERE."
- [laughs]
DID YOU WRITE THAT BEFOREHAND?
- YEAH, I HAD A FEW OTHERS.
LET'S SEE, UH...
"LOOKS LIKE YOU GUYS SHOULD
PUT MORE 'TRY' IN TRIAD," HUH?
OR, "WHEN YOU GET TO JAIL,
TELL 'EM MAKO SENT YA."
- OOH, I LIKE THAT ONE.
- OKAY, I'LL USE THAT
NEXT TIME.
BEIFONG SAYS
IF I KEEP IT UP,
I COULD MAKE DETECTIVE
SOON.
- OH, THAT SOUNDS SO FUN.
ALL I DO IS TRAIN
ALL DAY.
IT'S LIKE TENZIN'S TOTALLY
FORGOTTEN HOW I BEAT AMON.
- TENZIN'S JUST TRYING
TO HELP YOU BECOME
THE BEST AVATAR YOU CAN BE.
- OF COURSE
YOU'D TAKE HIS SIDE.
- I'M NOT TAKING HIS SIDE.
I'M JUST--
- I'M GONNA TAKE A WALK.
- WHY IS IT SO MUCH EASIER
TO BUST TRIADS
THAN IT IS TO GET THROUGH
ONE CONVERSATION
WITH MY GIRLFRIEND?
- GRAN-GRAN!
- OH, YOU'VE ALL
GOTTEN SO BIG.
- WE MISSED YOU, AUNT KYA.
- OH, I MISSED YOU TOO.
YOUR FATHER DOESN'T BRING YOU
TO VISIT NEARLY ENOUGH.
HE'S PROBABLY SCARED
I'LL BEAT HIM UP
LIKE WHEN WE WERE KIDS.
- I'M NOT SCARED OF YOU...
ANYMORE.
- YOU REMEMBER MAKO.
- SIR.
- I HOPE YOU'RE
NOT GETTING MY DAUGHTER
INTO ANY MORE TROUBLE
UP IN THE CITY.
- UH, NO.
I, UH--NO.
- KNOCK IT OFF, DAD.
- [chuckles]
- WOW,
LOOK AT ALL THESE PEOPLE
THAT CAME OUT TO GREET US.
- UH, NO.
THEY CAME TO GREET THEM.
[cheers and applause]
- THE GREAT CHIEF
OF THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE
COMES TO GRACE US
WITH HIS PRESENCE.
[mockingly]
HOORAY.
- JUST RELAX, TONRAQ.
HE'LL BE GONE SOON ENOUGH.
- [grumbles]
[bird squawks]
- WHOA, WHO ARE
THE LOVELY LADIES?
- THAT'S ESKA AND DESNA,
THE CHIEF'S CHILDREN.
DESNA IS A GUY.
- [laughs] OH, NO, SURE.
I KNEW THAT.
AND WHICH ONE IS DESNA?
- GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
AVATAR KORRA.
- GOOD TO SEE YOU TOO.
- TONRAQ.
- BROTHER.
- IT'S A SHAME THE SOUTHERNERS
HAVE ABANDONED
ALL CONNECTIONS
TO THE SPIRITS,
EVEN DURING
THE MOST HALLOWED TIMES.
- I'VE ALWAYS LOVED
THE GLACIER SPIRITS FESTIVAL.
IT'S FUN.
- THIS FESTIVAL
USED TO BE A SOLEMN TIME
OF FASTING AND MEDITATION.
NOW IT'S JUST A CHANCE
TO WATCH SOME RUBE
TRY TO STICK AN ENTIRE
ARCTIC HEN IN HIS MOUTH.
- [muffled]
WHA--WHAT? IT'S SO GOOD.
- TRADITIONS CHANGE.
IT'S NOT THE END
OF THE WORLD.
- TELL THAT TO THE SAILORS
WHO ARE BEING ATTACKED
BY ANGRY SPIRITS
IN SOUTHERN WATERS.
SOME TRADITIONS
HAVE PURPOSE.
- WAIT,
SPIRITS ARE ATTACKING SHIPS?
- I'M SURPRISED THE AVATAR
DOESN'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
APPARENTLY
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN GIVEN
ALL THE INFORMATION
YOU NEED.
IT WOULD BE MY HONOR
TO INSTRUCT YOU
IN THE SPIRITUAL WAYS
OF THE WATER TRIBE.
- I WOULDN'T MIND LEARNING
ABOUT FIGHTING SPIRITS.
AIRBENDING IS GETTING
PRETTY BORING.
- TENZIN IS
KORRA'S INSTRUCTOR.
HE CAN GIVE HER
ALL THE TRAINING SHE NEEDS.
- SO YOU'VE SAID.
- I'M GLAD YOU CAME WITH ME
TO THIS MEETING.
VARRICK IS ONE OF
THE RICHEST MEN IN THE WORLD,
AND HE CONTROLS THE ENTIRE
GLOBAL SHIPPING BUSINESS.
SO YOU'RE MY ASSISTANT.
JUST STAND THERE
AND DON'T SAY ANYTHING.
[Pabu chitters]
- NO PROBLEM.
PABU AND I
ARE NATURAL ASSISTANTS.
MAN, THIS IS NICE.
I GOTTA GET INTO
THIS WHOLE "BUSINESS" THING.
- DID YOU SEE THAT?
LEVITATION!
[laughs]
I WAS A FOOT OFF THE GROUND.
IS THAT INCREDIBLE
OR WHAT?
- HOW DOES HE DO THAT?
- THAT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
- WHAT?
IT LOOKED LIKE YOU
WERE JUST SITTING ON A PILLOW.
- [gasps]
[all gasp]
- ARE YOU SAYING
I WASN'T LEVITATING?
- [gulps]
UH, NO?
- WELL, WHY DIDN'T ANYONE
TELL ME?
NOW I LOOK LIKE AN IDIOT!
SWAMI, YOU'RE FIRED!
- AAH!
- I LIKE YOU, KID.
YOU'RE A REAL STRAIGHT SHOOTER,
JUST LIKE ME.
MS. SATO? HE'S WITH YOU?
- MM-HMM.
- BROUGHT YOUR TIGER-SHARK
WITH YOU TO DO BUSINESS, HUH?
NOW THAT'S MOXIE.
[laughs]
GET OVER HERE
AND POP A SQUAT.
ZHU LI, GET SOME TEA
FOR MY GUESTS.
- THANK YOU
FOR MEETING WITH ME.
AS YOU KNOW, FUTURE INDUSTRIES
IS LOOKING FOR A PARTNER
TO HANDLE OUR SHIPPING--
- SURE.
BUT FIRST,
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT
MY NEW VENTURE:
MOVING PICTURES.
ZHU LI, DO THE THING.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
MIND-BLOWING, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
- NOW, FORGET THAT!
THAT'S THE PAST!
SHUT IT OFF, ZHU LI!
IMAGINE WATCHING THIS.
GINGER, COME OVER HERE
AND DO YOUR POSES.
- [gasps]
[sultry music]
♪ ♪
- SPECTACULAR.
AND WE TELL A STORY.
THERE'S ROMANCE, ACTION,
SOME FUNNY ANIMAL STUFF
FOR THE KIDS.
YOU KNOW, WHATEVER.
THANKS, GINGER.
GO REST YOUR GAMS.
HOW ABOUT THAT, TIGER-SHARK?
WE'RE GONNA DO BIG BUSINESS
WITH THESE "MOVERS,"
AS I CALL 'EM.
- OKAY. BUT I'M JUST
CONCENTRATING ON GETTING FUTURE
INDUSTRIES BACK ON TRACK.
IF WE COULD
HAMMER OUT A DEAL--
- STOP.
LOOK ME IN THE EYE.
WE GOT A DEAL!
[all cheering]
WE'LL HAMMER OUT THE DETAILS
AT THE ROYAL FEAST TONIGHT.
NOW WHO WANTS
A ROCKET-BOAT RIDE?
[all cheering]
- IS THAT HOW BUSINESS
USUALLY GOES?
- YOU ARE
A NATURAL ASSISTANT.
- THIS IS A WONDERFUL FEAST
IN YOUR HONOR, UNCLE.
- THIS IS NOTHING.
WHEN THIS FESTIVAL
WAS FOUNDED,
THE TRIBAL ELDERS WOULD COMMUNE
WITH THE SPIRITS.
PEOPLE WOULD WATCH
THE BRILLIANT DISPLAYS OF LIGHT
AS SPIRITS
DANCED IN THE SKY.
- WOW.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT.
- AND THAT IS A SHAME,
SINCE THE AVATAR
IS THE BRIDGE
BETWEEN THE MATERIAL WORLD
AND THE SPIRITS.
THAT IS WHY I WANT SO BADLY
TO TEACH YOU,
TO HELP YOU FULFILL
YOUR DESTINY.
- I THOUGHT
I HAD MADE IT CLEAR
THAT TENZIN
IS TEACHING HER.
- EVERY AVATAR BEFORE YOU
TRAVELED THE WORLD TO LEARN.
IT WAS TENZIN AND YOUR FATHER
WHO KEPT YOU SECLUDED
AT THE SOUTH POLE.
- I THOUGHT AANG
ORDERED THE WHITE LOTUS
TO KEEP ME DOWN HERE?
- WE ALL DID WHAT
WE THOUGHT WAS BEST FOR YOU.
- WHO I TRAIN WITH
SHOULD BE MY DECISION, DAD,
NOT YOURS OR TENZIN'S.
- LOOKS LIKE SOMEONE'S
TRYING TO TAKE YOUR PLACE
AS THE AVATAR'S
STICK-IN-THE-MUD MENTOR.
- BUMI,
DON'T PICK ON TENZIN.
YOU KNOW
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN SENSITIVE.
- I'M NOT SENSITIVE!
[both laughing]
- AS YOUR CHIEF,
IT IS MY HONOR TO SPEAK
AT THIS FESTIVAL,
WHICH WAS FOUNDED
TO BRING OUR TRIBES
TOGETHER
AND RESTORE
THE ANCIENT BALANCE
BETWEEN OUR WORLD
AND THAT OF THE SPIRITS.
BUT I AM SADDENED TO SEE
WHAT IT HAS BECOME--
A CHEAP CARNIVAL THAT CELEBRATES
GREEDY AND TRIVIAL HUMANS.
- [teeth squeaking]
- I FEAR THE TIME
IS FAST APPROACHING
WHEN THE NORTH CAN NO LONGER
STAND IDLY BY
WHILE OUR SOUTHERN BROTHERS
SLIP INTO TOTAL SPIRITUAL DECAY.
ANGRY SPIRITS ARE ALREADY
ATTACKING SHIPS
IN YOUR WATERS.
I ONLY HOPE
WE ARE NOT TOO LATE
TO CHANGE COURSE.
[all murmuring]
- CHIEF UNALAQ, EVERYBODY.
ALWAYS GREAT
TO HAVE HIM IN TOWN.
NOW LET'S HAVE SOME FUN
WITH WACKY WUSHU'S
DANCIN' OTTER-PENGUINS.
[energetic music]
♪ ♪
[carnival music]
- [giggles]
- MM-MM.
- [clears throat]
WISH ME LUCK.
I'M MAKING MY MOVE.
WHEE!
- GOOD LUCK.
- THOSE TWO
HAVE ALWAYS CREEPED ME OUT.
THEY SMELL LIKE
A GRANDMA'S ATTIC.
- HEY, I'M BOLIN.
I'M A FRIEND OF KORRA'S.
YOU'RE ESKA, RIGHT?
WOW, I'M JUST--
I'M LOVING THESE ROBES.
- [hisses]
- [clears throat]
SO YOU ARE FROM THE NORTH,
RIGHT? COOL.
THAT'S LIKE--
YOU KNOW, THAT'S, LIKE,
MY FAVORITE DIRECTION.
- I THINK HE IS TRYING
TO ESTABLISH
SOME KIND OF BOND WITH YOU
BASED ON YOUR GEOGRAPHIC
POINT OF ORIGIN.
- PERHAPS IT
WOULD BE INTERESTING
TO SPEND TIME
WITH A PERSON
WHOSE WAYS ARE SO ROUGH
AND UNCULTURED.
YOU AMUSE ME.
I WILL MAKE YOU MINE.
- YOU MEAN LIKE A BOYFRIEND
OR--OR LIKE A SLAVE?
- YES.
WIN ME PRIZES.
- [laughs nervously]
[bell dings]
- UNALAQ OFFERED TO TRAIN ME.
HE SAYS HE CAN TEACH ME
ABOUT THE SPIRITS
AND MY CONNECTION TO THEM.
- SOUNDS GOOD.
WHAT DOES TENZIN THINK?
- TENZIN THINKS
I'M HIS PRISONER
OR ONE OF HIS KIDS.
I'LL NEVER FINISH TRAINING
WITH HIM IN CHARGE.
[bell dings]
- WE HAVE A WINNER.
- I MEAN, YOU HEARD
WHAT UNALAQ SAID.
THE SOUTH IS
SPIRITUALLY UNBALANCED,
AND IT'S THE AVATAR'S JOB
TO FIX IT.
BUT MY DAD
WON'T EVEN LET ME
THINK ABOUT
UNALAQ TEACHING ME.
WELL?
- WELL, WHAT?
- WHAT DO YOU THINK
I SHOULD DO?
- I GUESS YOU SHOULD DO
WHAT YOU THINK IS RIGHT.
I SUPPORT WHATEVER DECISION
YOU MAKE.
- OH, THANKS.
THAT'S A BIG HELP.
- I THOUGHT YOU WANTED ME
TO BE SUPPORTIVE.
NOW YOU WANT ME
TO TELL YOU WHAT I THINK?
MAKE UP YOUR MIND.
OOF!
- JUST FORGET IT.
[bells chiming]
UGH.
NAGA,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[Naga howling]
NAGA, HUSH.
[howling continues]
QUIET, NAGA.
YOU'LL WAKE EVERYONE UP.
[Naga howling]
- [yawns]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- WHAT IS THAT?
UGH!
[groans]
[spirit growls]
- [groans]
- GOT IT!
DON'T GOT IT!
[both groaning]
- KORRA!
AAH!
[screams]
[groans]
- AAH!
- SPIRIT,
WHY ARE YOU ANGRY WITH US?
WHAT HAVE WE DONE
TO OFFEND YOU?
[groans]
- [grunts]
- GO IN PEACE.
- KORRA,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- HOW WERE YOU ABLE
TO CONTROL THAT SPIRIT
WHEN NO ONE ELSE COULD?
- AS YOUR FATHER
COULD TELL YOU,
I HAVE SPENT MY LIFE
STUDYING THE SPIRITS
AND LEARNING THEIR WAYS.
ALL OF THIS KNOWLEDGE
IS LOST IN THE SOUTH,
BUT I COULD TEACH YOU
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
- CHIEF UNALAQ, CLEARLY,
YOU ARE VERY KNOWLEDGEABLE,
BUT KORRA STILL HAS MUCH
TO LEARN ABOUT AIRBENDING,
AND I HOPE THAT GOING
TO THE AIR TEMPLES
WILL HELP HER CONNECT
WITH THE PAST AVATARS.
- UGH!
- THE AIR TEMPLES
WILL TEACH HER NOTHING.
ONLY I CAN GIVE HER
THE TRAINING SHE NEEDS
TO BE A COMPLETE AVATAR.
- I'VE TOLD YOU
THAT WILL NOT HAPPEN.
- HEY,
I'M RIGHT HERE!
ANYONE WANT TO ASK ME
WHAT I THINK?
- KORRA, PLEASE, LISTEN.
- I'M TIRED OF LISTENING
TO YOU--BOTH OF YOU.
YOU KEEP ME LOCKED UP,
TELLING ME
YOU KNOW WHAT'S BEST,
BUT BOTH OF
YOU WERE POWERLESS
AGAINST THE SPIRIT ATTACK.
I THINK IT'S TIME
I HAD A NEW TEACHER.
- NOW, KORRA--
- UNALAQ HAS PROVEN
HE'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO KNOWS
WHAT I NEED TO LEARN.
I HAVE TO GO WITH HIM.
- PLEASE,
I KNOW YOU'RE ANGRY,
BUT WE'VE COME
SO FAR TOGETHER.
- I'M SORRY, TENZIN.
THIS IS AS FAR AS WE GO.
- IT HAS BEEN
A PLEASURE SERVING YOU,
AVATAR KORRA.
- I THINK YOU FORGOT
A COUPLE OF THINGS.
- MOTHER, I THINK
I NEED SOME TIME ALONE
WITH MY FAMILY
RIGHT NOW.
- THIS IS YOUR FAMILY,
TENZIN.
WHEN YOU
GET TO BE MY AGE,
YOU'LL BE THANKFUL
FOR THE TIME YOU HAD
WITH YOUR SIBLINGS.
BESIDES,
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT YOU ALL VISIT
YOUR FATHER'S HOME TOGETHER.
- COME ON, IT'LL BE FUN.
- I'M DYING TO SEE THAT
LAID-BACK "VACATION TENZIN"
I'VE HEARD SO MUCH ABOUT.
- ALL RIGHT.
HOP ON.
I LOVE YOU, MOM.
WE'LL SEE YOU SOON.
- [grunts]
OH!
- DO YOU THINK
I DID THE RIGHT THING?
- [sighs]
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M SORRY,
BUT I'M NOT VERY GOOD
AT THIS AVATAR
COUNSELING THING.
BUT I KNOW YOUR HEART
IS IN THE RIGHT PLACE.
YOU'LL JUST HAVE
TO TRUST IT.
- I KNOW THIS WAS
A HARD DECISION, KORRA.
BUT IT WAS THE RIGHT ONE.
NOW IT IS TIME TO PUT IT
BEHIND YOU
AND BEGIN
YOUR NEW TRAINING.
I HAVE GREAT
PLANS FOR YOU.
[gentle instrumental music]
♪ ♪