- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE
IS UNDER SIEGE.
WHEN AVATAR KORRA
WAS ATTACKED BY A DARK SPIRIT,
CHIEF UNALAQ WAS THE ONLY ONE
ABLE TO STOP IT.
SO KORRA TURNED
HER BACK ON TENZIN
AND CHOSE UNALAQ
AS HER NEW SPIRITUAL MENTOR.
TENZIN AND HIS FAMILY
LEFT FOR A VACATION
AT THE SOUTHERN AIR TEMPLE,
WHILE KORRA REMAINED
IN THE WATER TRIBE.
WILL SHE BE ABLE
TO RESTORE BALANCE
BETWEEN HUMANS AND SPIRITS?
- YOU'RE EARLY.
- WHAT CAN I SAY?
I'M PUMPED UP TO LEARN
THAT UNALAQ SPIRIT FIGHTING.
- I'M NOT HERE TO TEACH YOU
TO FIGHT SPIRITS.
I'M HERE TO HELP YOU
BEGIN YOUR SPIRITUAL TRAINING.
WE'RE GOING TO ONE OF THE MOST
REMOTE PLACES IN THE WORLD--
THE LONG-NEGLECTED
SPIRITUAL CENTER OF YOUR TRIBE:
THE SOUTH POLE.
- YOU'RE GONNA TRAIN ME
AT THE SOUTH POLE?
- WE WILL DO MORE
THAN JUST TRAIN.
BY NEGLECTING THE SPIRITS,
THE PEOPLE OF THE SOUTH
HAVE BROUGHT DARKNESS
UPON THEMSELVES,
AND NOW IT THREATENS
TO DESTROY OUR TRIBE.
WE MUST SET THINGS RIGHT.
THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE
DEPENDS ON YOU.
- A DANGEROUS TRIP
TO THE SOUTH POLE?
COUNT ME IN.
- THERE IT IS,
THE SOUTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
ISN'T IT MAGNIFICENT?
- MASTER TENZIN, WELCOME.
- GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
ABBOT SHUNG.
- IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU NEED?
WATER?
DANDELION GREENS?
AH, PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE
TO RE-CENTER YOURSELF
BY MEDITATING
IN THE GARDENS.
- NO, THANK YOU.
I'M FINE.
- AND YOU MUST
BE THE HONORABLE PEMA.
PLEASE,
ACCEPT THESE GIFTS.
THIS IS AN ANCIENT
AIRBENDER HEAD SHAVER
WE'VE REFURBISHED
JUST FOR YOU.
- OH...OKAY.
- AND PEMA, THESE FLOWERS
ONCE FILLED THE MOUNTAINSIDE.
NOW THEY CAN
BRIGHTEN UP YOUR ROOM.
- THAT'S...SWEET?
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO.
- NONSENSE.
WHATEVER YOU NEED
IS YOURS.
ANYTHING FOR THE MOTHER
OF THE NEXT GENERATION
OF AIRBENDERS.
- NO! THAT GIFT IS MINE.
- YOU DON'T EVEN LIKE TO READ.
- NAAH.
- YEP, THOSE ARE THE WORLD'S
NEXT GENERATION OF AIRBENDERS.
- MOMMY, DADDY, LOOK.
I FINALLY GOT A LEMUR.
I'M GONNA NAME HIM POKI.
POKI, COME BACK!
- UGH.
PHEW.
EXCUSE ME,
A LITTLE HELP HERE.
- SORRY, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE THE SERVANTS.
- WE'RE TENZIN'S
BROTHER AND SISTER.
- AVATAR AANG
HAD OTHER CHILDREN?
THE WORLD IS FILLED
WITH MORE AIRBENDERS?
- WE'RE NOT AIRBENDERS.
- OH.
I'M SO SORRY.
- I THOUGHT YOU SAID
BOLIN WAS COMING.
- HE SAID HE'D BE HERE,
BUT I CAN'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I HAVE TO MAKE SURE
YOU HAVE EVERYTHING YOU NEED
FOR A SAFE TRIP.
- THANKS, CAPTAIN EXPEDITION,
BUT I'LL BE FINE.
[engine hums]
- TONRAQ,
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- I HEARD YOU'RE TAKING
KORRA TO THE SOUTH POLE.
I'M COMING.
- ABSOLUTELY NOT.
YOU'RE A DISTRACTION
TO KORRA
AND A HINDRANCE
TO WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
MY DAUGHTER
IS NOT GOING WITHOUT ME.
SHE NEEDS SOMEONE
TO WATCH AFTER HER.
- DAD, WHY DO YOU ALWAYS THINK
YOU KNOW WHAT'S BEST FOR ME?
- BECAUSE HE'S MISGUIDED.
THE SAD TRUTH IS
IT'S MEN LIKE YOUR FATHER
WHO HAVE PUT THE SPIRIT WORLD
OUT OF BALANCE.
HE'S IGNORED MY WARNINGS
IN THE PAST
AND HASN'T LEARNED SINCE.
- WHAT HAPPENED IN THE PAST?
- IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WHAT MATTERS
IS THE EVERSTORM.
- THE EVERSTORM?
- IT'S A MASSIVE BLIZZARD
THAT'S BATTERED
THE SOUTH POLE FOR DECADES.
I'M COMING, UNLESS YOU THINK
YOU CAN STOP ME.
- GUYS!
HEY, WAIT FOR ME!
CHECK IT OUT.
I'M TRAVELING IN STYLE.
[engine revs]
WHOA!
OKAY, I'M SORRY.
STILL GETTING USED
TO THAT THROTTLE.
- UH, WHERE'D YOU
GET THE RIDE?
- VARRICK.
HE'S AWESOME.
HE ALSO GAVE ME
THIS FANCY SNOWSUIT.
IT'S INFLATABLE
WITH AN INTERNAL HEATER,
EMERGENCY BEACON,
AND FOOD RATION POUCH.
I MEAN, IF I GET LOST,
I CAN SURVIVE IN THIS THING
FOR, LIKE,
LIKE, A MONTH.
WHO WANTS SOME FREEZE-DRIED
CUCUMBER-QUATS?
NOBODY?
DID I INTERRUPT
A CONVERSATION?
[Pabu squeaks]
- NO, THE CONVERSATION
IS OVER.
DAD, COME IF YOU WANT.
JUST DON'T INTERFERE
WITH MY TRAINING.
- DOES THIS SIDECAR HAVE
THE CAPACITY FOR TWO PASSENGERS?
- SURE DOES.
BUT, UH, WHO'S GONNA DRIVE?
[engine humming]
- WELL, WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
LOOKS LIKE--
- GO AWAY, MAKO.
- SO ONCE WE GET TO THE SOUTH
POLE, THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
- YOU WILL OPEN
AN ANCIENT SPIRIT PORTAL.
- I'M SORRY.
WHAT NOW?
- AT THE SOUTH POLE,
THERE IS A PORTAL
THAT CONNECTS OUR WORLD
TO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
BUT IT HAS LONG BEEN CLOSED.
- AND THAT'S WHY
THE EVIL SPIRITS ARE ATTACKING?
- THERE ARE NO EVIL SPIRITS.
[lightning cracks]
THERE IS LIGHT
AND DARK IN THEM ALL.
BUT WHEN THEY'RE UNBALANCED,
THE DARKNESS TAKES OVER.
IF YOU CAN OPEN
THE PORTAL IN TIME,
BALANCE WILL BE RESTORED.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN
"IN TIME"?
- THERE'S A REASON
THE GLACIER SPIRITS FESTIVAL
ENDS ON THE WINTER SOLSTICE.
THAT'S WHEN THE SPIRIT WORLD
AND THE PHYSICAL WORLD
ARE CLOSE TOGETHER.
- ONLY THEN CAN THE AVATAR
OPEN THE PORTAL.
- THE WINTER SOLSTICE
IS TOMORROW.
- EXACTLY.
AND WE CAN'T AFFORD
TO WAIT ANOTHER YEAR.
[spirit hisses]
[growls]
- EASY, NAGA.
[continues growling]
- WHAT ARE THOSE?
- DARK SPIRITS.
- LET'S KEEP MOVING.
WE HAVE TO FIND
A SAFE PLACE TO SET UP CAMP.
- UNCLE, WHY DO YOU THINK
THE DARK SPIRITS
ARE FOLLOWING US?
- CAN WE NOT TALK
ABOUT DARK SPIRITS, PLEASE?
- MY BROTHER
DOESN'T LIKE GHOST STORIES.
- DON'T WORRY.
I WILL PROTECT YOU,
MY FEEBLE TURTLE-DUCK.
- THANK YOU.
- SADLY,
THIS ISN'T A GHOST STORY.
THIS IS REAL.
- [gasps]
- THE SPIRITS ARE ANGRY
BECAUSE HE'S HERE.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER WONDERED
HOW YOUR FATHER
ENDED UP
IN THE SOUTH POLE?
WHY HE'S NEVER TAKEN YOU TO
VISIT HIS HOMELAND IN THE NORTH?
- UNALAQ,
THIS IS NOT THE TIME.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU SHOULD HAVE TOLD HER
A LONG TIME AGO.
- TOLD ME WHAT?
- I LEFT THE NORTH POLE
BECAUSE...
I WAS BANISHED.
- YOU WERE BANISHED
FROM THE NORTH? WHY?
- BECAUSE I ALMOST DESTROYED
THE ENTIRE TRIBE.
20 YEARS AGO, I WAS A GENERAL
IN THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE,
SWORN TO PROTECT MY PEOPLE.
- BROTHER,
WE'RE BEING ATTACKED.
[pained grunts]
[scattered screaming]
[water rushing]
I DROVE THEM OUT OF THE CITY
AND DEEP INTO THE FROZEN TUNDRA.
[battle cries]
WE TRACKED THEM DEEP
INTO AN ANCIENT FOREST.
MANY BELIEVED THIS FOREST
WAS THE HOME TO SPIRITS,
AND THE BARBARIANS
RETREATED THERE
BECAUSE THEY THOUGHT
WE WOULDN'T ATTACK
ON SUCH HALLOWED GROUNDS.
THEY THOUGHT WRONG.
[all scream]
- [grunts]
- WE CAPTURED THE BARBARIANS,
BUT IN THE PROCESS,
WE DESTROYED THE FOREST.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
THE CONSEQUENCES
OF WHAT I HAD DONE.
[monstrous hissing]
BY DESTROYING THE FOREST,
I UNKNOWINGLY
LET LOOSE ANGRY SPIRITS.
[both scream]
THEY THREATENED
TO DESTROY EVERYTHING.
THE ENTIRE CITY.
UNALAQ WAS ABLE TO GUIDE
THE SPIRITS BACK TO THE FOREST,
BUT BY THEN,
THE DAMAGE HAD BEEN DONE.
FOR BEING THE CAUSE
OF SO MUCH DEVASTATION,
MY FATHER BANISHED ME
FROM THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE
IN SHAME.
THAT'S WHEN I CAME TO THE SOUTH
AND STARTED A NEW LIFE.
- WHOA.
SO YOU WERE
SUPPOSED TO BE CHIEF,
THEN HE BECAME CHIEF.
NO WONDER YOU GUYS
DON'T LIKE EACH OTHER.
OW! WHAT?
ISN'T THAT WHAT HAPPENED?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU KEPT THIS FROM ME.
- I WAS PROTECTING YOU
FROM THE SHAME
I BROUGHT ON THE FAMILY.
- WHY DO YOU KEEP
HIDING THINGS FROM ME
AND THEN TELLING ME
IT'S FOR MY OWN PROTECTION?
I'M TIRED OF YOU
PROTECTING ME.
- KORRA.
- WOW.
THE STATUE ROOM.
- THAT'S RIGHT, JINORA.
THE MOST SACRED PLACE IN
THE ENTIRE SOUTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
HERE YOU WILL FIND STATUES
OF EVERY AVATAR WHO EVER LIVED.
WHERE ARE YOUR BROTHER
AND SISTER?
[excited shouts]
- YOU CAN'T CATCH ME.
I'M THE GREATEST AIR SKATER
OF ALL TIME.
OOF!
[rock crumbles]
- MEELO!
- KORRA, YOU HAVE EVERY RIGHT
TO BE MAD AT ME,
BUT I DON'T WANT YOU TO MAKE
THE SAME MISTAKE I MADE.
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER
GONE INTO THAT FOREST,
AND WE SHOULDN'T BE GOING
TO THE SOUTH POLE NOW.
SPIRITS AND THE PHYSICAL WORLD
SHOULD REMAIN SEPARATE.
- DAD, IT'S MY JOB
TO BE THE BRIDGE
BETWEEN THE SPIRITS
AND THE PHYSICAL WORLD,
AND I FINALLY HAVE A CHANCE
TO LIVE UP TO MY POTENTIAL.
- YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF WHAT UNALAQ SAYS IS TRUE.
- YOU WANT PROOF?
LOOK TO THE SKY.
WHERE I'M FROM,
THE SPIRITS ARE AT PEACE
AND THEY LIGHT UP THE DARK.
- THE NORTHERN LIGHTS.
- YES.
THERE USED TO BE LIGHTS
IN THE SOUTH AS WELL.
BUT DURING THE 100 YEAR WAR,
THE SOUTH WAS THROWN
OUT OF BALANCE
AND THE LIGHTS
DISAPPEARED.
WHEN THE WAR ENDED,
THE NORTH HELPED
TO REBUILD YOU PHYSICALLY
AS A NATION.
BUT WE HAVE NOT
REBUILT YOU SPIRITUALLY.
NOW THE SPIRITS
NO LONGER DANCE IN YOUR SKIES.
INSTEAD, THEY RAMPAGE
IN THE EVERSTORM.
- I THINK WE'RE HERE.
[thunder rumbles]
[spirit hisses]
- IS THAT WHAT I THINK IT IS?
- WE MUST KEEP MOVING.
[spirits roar]
- OH, MAN.
I REALLY DON'T LIKE THIS.
- BOLIN, JUST STAY CALM.
THERE'S NO REASON TO--
PANIC!
- [yelps]
- [grunts]
- AAH!
- KORRA, LOOK OUT!
[grunts]
- OH, IT'S IN THE ENGINE!
[screams]
[mystical music]
♪ ♪
[spirit roars]
- [grunts]
- IS EVERYONE OKAY?
- [screams]
I CAN'T STOP IT.
- I'LL SAVE YOU.
- [screams]
[explosion]
[grunts]
I'M A RAFT!
UH, CAN SOMEONE
PLEASE DEFLATE ME?
[air hisses,
Pabu squeaks]
THANK YOU.
- OH, GREAT.
THERE GOES OUR EQUIPMENT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO DO?
- THERE'S ONLY ONE THING
TO DO.
WE HAVE TO TURN BACK.
- NO.
THE SOLSTICE IS TONIGHT.
WE'RE SO CLOSE.
- THIS MISSION
IS TOO DANGEROUS.
WE'RE LEAVING.
- NO, DAD.
YOU'RE LEAVING.
- DON'T WORRY, SIR.
I'LL KEEP AN EYE
ON KORRA FOR YOU.
- THANK YOU, MAKO.
[engine revs]
- LET'S OPEN THIS PORTAL
AND LEAD YOUR FATHER
AND THE ENTIRE
SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
- THEN WHAT ARE WE
WAITING FOR?
SO, WHAT EXACTLY WERE
YOU AND MY DAD TALKING ABOUT?
- NOTHING.
HE WAS JUST WORRIED
ABOUT YOU, THAT'S ALL.
- YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES
I WONDER WHOSE SIDE YOU'RE ON.
- THERE AREN'T ANY SIDES.
WE ALL JUST WANT
TO HELP HOWEVER WE CAN.
YOU HAVE TO TRUST
THAT WE'RE HERE FOR YOU.
- WE'VE ARRIVED.
- TREES FROZEN IN ICE.
- IT'S JUST LIKE
THE SACRED FOREST
TONRAQ DESTROYED
IN THE NORTH.
- SO WHAT DO I DO?
- YOU MUST FIND YOUR WAY
TO THE HEART OF THE FOREST
WHERE THE DORMANT
SPIRIT PORTAL LIES.
FROM HERE,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
- WAIT A SECOND.
THERE'S NO WAY
SHE'S GOING ALONE.
- YEAH, IF SHE GOES,
WE GO TOO.
- THE AVATAR MUST GO ALONE.
- BUT I DON'T HAVE ANY
CONNECTION WITH THE SPIRITS.
IN FACT, IT SEEMS
LIKE THEY HATE ME.
- YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE IN
YOURSELF LIKE I BELIEVE IN YOU.
WHAT IS IT?
- I GUESS I'M JUST
SO USED TO PEOPLE
TELLING ME HOW TO DO THINGS
THAT I FORGOT WHAT IT WAS LIKE
TO HAVE SOMEONE TRUST IN ME.
- KORRA, ALL THE PAST AVATARS
LIVE ON INSIDE OF YOU.
LET THEM GUIDE YOU.
LET THEM HELP YOU
FIND THE LIGHT IN THE DARK.
- WAIT HERE.
I'LL BE OKAY.
- GOOD LUCK.
[Pabu squeaks]
[wind howling]
[ghostly hissing]
- [gasps]
[panting]
[grunts]
THE SPIRIT PORTAL.
AMAZING.
- [gasps]
[mystical music]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
WHAT AVATAR IS THIS?
- THE LIGHT IN THE DARK.
[grunts]
- WHY ISN'T IT OPENING?
[gasps]
COME ON, PORTAL.
OPEN!
[spirit hisses]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[warbling chime, rumbling]
OOF!
THE SPIRITS
DANCING IN THE SKY.
- [gasps]
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
- IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
- SHE DID IT.
- HEY, KORRA, YOU'RE BACK!
HEY, KORRA'S BACK.
WHA--HUH?
- WHY ARE YOU INITIATING
PHYSICAL CONTACT
WITH ANOTHER WOMAN?
- [gulps and laughs nervously]
- EVERYTHING YOU SAID
WAS TRUE.
- AVATAR KORRA,
YOU HAVE TAKEN THE FIRST STEP
IN BRINGING BALANCE
BACK TO THE SOUTH,
AND SOON,
THE WHOLE WORLD.
- YOU NEVER CEASE TO AMAZE ME.
- THANKS.
BY THE WAY, I'M REALLY SORRY
FOR BEING A TOTAL PAIN.
THINGS WERE REALLY STRESSFUL
AND CONFUSING.
IT'S HARD BEING THE AVATAR.
- IT'S HARDER
BEING THE AVATAR'S BOYFRIEND.
- [laughs]
WHAT ARE ALL YOUR
NORTHERN TROOPS DOING HERE?
- OPENING THE SPIRIT PORTAL
WAS ONLY THE FIRST STEP
IN GETTING
THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE
BACK ON ITS RIGHTEOUS PATH.
THERE'S MORE DIFFICULT WORK
TO BE DONE
BEFORE OUR TWO TRIBES
ARE TRULY UNITED.