Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
Korra has reopened
the southern spirit portal
and taken the first step
to restoring balance
between spirits and man.
Meanwhile, tensions are high
between Korra and her father
after she discovered he was
hiding a dark secret--
years ago,
Tonraq was banished from the North.
And now the Northern navy
has landed on Southern shores.
What other plans does Unalaq
have for the Avatar?
Soldier: Everyone, clear the streets.
Get back in your homes.
- Uncle, why did you bring
your troops down from the North?
- Now that you've opened
the southern portal,
we need to protect it from people
who would do the spirits harm.
- I can protect it.
- I need you for something
more important.
There is another portal in the North.
Once you open it,
spirits and man will be able
to move freely
between the North and the South
in a matter of seconds.
- But the solstice is over.
How am I going to open it?
- The spiritual energy
is much stronger in the North.
And now that you've opened
the southern portal,
your energy is stronger as well.
- With both portals open,
our tribes will be united again.
- The world will be united again.
- Ahh, I haven't felt
this at peace since--
- Wahoo!
- And it's over.
- Good morning, universe!
- Bumi, please.
Cover yourself.
- Well, lookee here.
"Vacation Tenzin" has finally
decided to join us.
- Yes, he has.
It's so nice to get to spend more time
with my family.
Isn't that right,
my little Rohan?
- And I've really enjoyed
having you two around.
Reminds me of all those
great vacations we took
as kids with Dad.
- Uh, I think your memory
is a little foggy.
Bumi and I weren't
on those great vacations.
It was always just you and Dad.
- No, that can't be right.
What about the time he took us
to Kyoshi Island
to ride the elephant-koi?
- Nope.
We weren't there.
- Hmm.
Oh, remember Ember Island?
Those amazing sand palaces
we built on the beach?
- You mean you built.
We never saw the place.
- I could've sworn--
- Woo-hoo!
- Morning, kids.
- Morning, Uncle Bumi.
Do you have a baby in there?
- Where's your sister?
-' Who?
- Ikki. About this tall.
Talks real fast.
I'm sure you know her.
- Uh...
there was a lemur fight,
but the bison told us
not to worry
because a giant was coming.
Then we almost got eaten
by a shark-squid.
- The shark-squid?
He's here?
It appears my old nemesis
has found me.
- Jinora, were you and Meelo
teasing your sister again?
- I don't know.
Maybe. Yes.
- She ran away.
- Honestly, I don't know why
you kids can't just get along!
- It's all right, dear.
Ikki couldn't have gone far.
I'll find her.
- Commander Bumi reporting for duty!
Search-and-rescue missions
are my specialty.
- What do you say we all go together?
- Sure.
I could use the help.
- When I get back,
we'll come up with a plan
to take down that shark-squid
once and for all.
- Yeah!
- Thank you for coming, everyone.
I know these last few days
have been very troubling.
- Troubling?
Troubling is when I get
that itchy rash
that won't go away
and Zhu Li's not around to scratch it.
This is shocking.
Nay, sickening!
But these kale cookies?
Opposite.
Remind me to get the recipe later.
- What's your point, Varrick?
- My point is,
Unalaq's already booted
our chieftains
out of their palace.
How long before he starts telling us
what kind of cookies we can eat?
- Probably a couple of days.
- Rhetorical question, Zhu Li.
You gotta keep up.
Not to mention I've got
a cargo ship full of halibut
that's rotting,
thanks to this harbor lockdown.
Who wants to buy a ship full
of stinking fish?
Seriously, it's not rhetorical.
I need to sell these fish.
- Chief Unalaq is here
to help the South.
He wants to show us
how to restore balance
with the spirits
so they'll stop attacking.
- The only spirit
I'm interested in restoring
is our spirit of independence!
Am I right, people?
- All Unalaq is trying to do
is make our tribes unified again.
- No, he wants control of our wealth.
My wealth.
And I like my wealth.
If Unalaq doesn't pull
his forces out,
then we have no choice
but to fight for our freedom!
- You want to start a war?
Are you crazy?
- Unalaq started this, not us.
I'm sorry.
Maybe you could speak
with your uncle,
tell him how frustrated we all are.
He'll listen to what
the Avatar has to say.
Do it for me?
- I'll do it for the tribe.
- I cannot stop eating these things.
Look, we all know
where this conflict is heading.
We need to start preparing for war.
- I will hate to leave
this quaint tribe.
- Is that true, Eska?
- Of course not, Desna.
I will not miss it at all.
I hold immense dislike
for the South.
Bolin!
Laugh at my humorous quip.
- Yes, dear.
So--so funny.
You know,
I'll be really sad
when you have to leave.
It's been really great
getting to know you.
Really.
- But you will be coming
with me to the North.
There we will live
the rest of our lives together
in icy bliss.
Foolish Bolin.
- Mako!
I'm so happy to see you!
- Uh, you all right, bro?
- No!
No, I'm not all right!
I can't take any more.
Listen, I don't want to live
in icy bliss with Eska!
Don't make me!
Oh, please,
please don't make me.
- Uh, hey,
if you're that unhappy,
just break up with her.
- Break up with her?
You can do that?
- Yeah.
Guys do it all the time.
- How?
- Just tell her you're not
that into her anymore.
- Oh, no, no,
I don't think she'd like that.
- Ending a relationship is kind of like
pulling off a bloodsucking leech.
You just gotta rip it off
and get it over with.
You'll feel a lot better afterwards.
Trust me.
- Thanks, Mako.
Whew.
I'm lucky you're so good
at breaking girls' hearts.
Korra better watch out.
Ooh, no, it's just a--
uh, you kn--
uh, never mind.
- Our next training session
isn't until tomorrow.
- I'm sorry to interrupt.
It's about our conversation
this morning.
- Yes?
- I understand why
you brought your troops here,
but I'm afraid it's sending
the wrong message.
- Your father has been talking to you.
- Not just him.
Varrick too.
There was a meeting
at my parents' house.
A lot of Southerners feel
like their tribe
is being invaded.
- I am their chief.
I'm uniting, not invading.
- I know, but I'm just afraid
if something doesn't change,
there could be a civil war.
- If the Water Tribes were at war,
the other nations would take sides.
The dark spirits would thrive
off this negative energy,
and the world would be thrown
into a battle
between spirits and man
that would be catastrophic.
- How do we stop it?
- We?
No, Korra.
This is a war
only the Avatar can prevent.
- I'm usually the one starting fights.
I don't know how to stop them
from happening.
- As the Avatar,
you must remain neutral
in this conflict.
You will naturally want
to help your people,
but showing favoritism will not
help our tribes find unity.
- Maybe Tenzin was right.
Maybe I'm not ready
to be the Avatar.
- Tenzin lacked faith in you.
But I have no doubt
you will become
the most admired Avatar
the world has ever known.
- Thank you, Uncle.
- Who threw those?
You hoodlums think
you're tough, huh?
- Pick on a Waterbender
your own size!
- Stop!
- Tell these thugs
to go back to the North.
They're not welcome here anymore!
- These Southerners
need to stay in line.
- Everyone, calm down.
You're all part of the same tribe.
Start acting like it.
- You're taking their side?
We thought you were one of us.
- I'm not taking anyone's side.
Hey!
- You're the worst Avatar ever!
- Everyone, walk away from this.
They're not worth our trouble.
Go back to your homes.
Korra, I--
Korra!
- Ikki!
Ikki!
Ikki?
Ikki, where are you?
Over here, Dad!
Just kidding. It's me!
- There's no sign of her anywhere.
- Why would lkki run off like this?
Ah, it's probably my fault.
- Probably.
- Excuse me?
- I'm guessing you've been so busy
with your "duty" to Republic City
that you forgot about your duty
to your kids.
Duty.
- What are you, five years old?
- Kya, you're right.
I haven't been spending
enough time with them.
I wish I could be as good a father
as Dad was to us.
- Tenzin, your problem is
you're exactly like Dad.
He was so focused on saving the world
and doing his duty--
don't laugh--
that he never had time for us.
- Dad was under a lot of pressure.
- He always had time
for you, though,
his precious little Airbender.
- Dad loved us all equally.
Besides, it all happened
a long time ago.
Why are we even talking
about this?
- Because you seem to have
some grandiose delusion
that we had a perfect,
happy-go-lucky childhood.
Guess what.
We didn't.
- We need to keep moving
if we want to find lkki before dark.
- See what he's doing there, Bumi?
Classic Airbender technique.
Cutting and running
when things get tough!
- Ugh.
- Yeah.
Did Dad teach you that move?
- How was your day, sweetie?
- Oh, fabulous.
My tribe's about to go to war,
and I'm supposed to stop it,
but will anyone listen to me?
No! And I didn't ask
for my father's help.
Can't he just let me be the Avatar?
- Uh, do you want advice,
or am I just supposed to listen?
I'm still not clear on that.
- Ugh. I'm sorry.
My dad just gets me all worked up.
- How about you take a break
from all this Avatar stuff,
and we go out for a quiet dinner?
Just the two of us.
Isn't this fun, huh?
We never get to spend
enough time together,
just the five of us.
So fun.
- Excuse us while we retrieve
more sustenance.
- You guys gotta save me.
- I thought you were
breaking up with her.
What happened
to ripping off the leech?
- I tried!
But any time I bring up the subject,
she threatens to freeze me
in a block of ice
and feed me to dolphin-piranhas!
- So it was more like
you tugged at the leech.
- Yes, over and over and over,
but it won't come off.
Why didn't you warn me
your cousin had the power
to reach into my heart
and crush my soul
with her bare hands?
- Uh, 'cause I thought
it was pretty obvious.
- No, no,
not to me, it wasn't.
I'm very bad at reading people.
You should know that by now.
Oh, man.
Oh!
Do something, Avatar!
- You know, this reminds me
of a search-and-rescue mission
I commanded years ago
in the mountains outside of Ba Sing Se.
Here we go.
- For five days, we scoured
that beast of a mountain,
fighting our way
through blizzards, sandstorms,
and three typhoons.
Finally, we found the men
huddled in a cave,
seconds from death.
With no time to lose,
I piled all 12 of those
poor souls on my back
and single-handedly carried them
down the mountain to safety.
- And how exactly is that
supposed to help us find lkki?
- It was supposed to inspire you.
Clearly, you know nothing
about being a leader of men.
That's probably why
the Avatar fired you.
- I'm sick of your far-fetched tales.
Three typhoons?
- Well, I may have thrown in
an extra typhoon or two
for dramatic effect, but--
- Quit arguing and bring
that lantern over here.
I found footprints!
- Come on!
- No, follow me!
This will get us down
50 times faster.
- Bumi, it's pitch black,
and the rocks are slippery.
You're gonna hurt yourself.
- Come on, you wimps!
If I can do it,
it should be no problem
for a couple of benders.
- Fine.
- You were right, Bumi!
That was faster!
- At least 50 times faster,
by my calculations.
- Oh, Tenzin's
the funny guy now.
- If you need an airlift down,
just say the word.
- Bah, I don't need your help.
I've got everything under control.
Agh!
- Bumi!
- Did Dad send you to talk to me?
- Your father doesn't know I'm here.
Korra, what's going on
between you two?
- Ask Dad.
- I've tried,
but he won't talk about it.
Honey, it breaks my heart
to see our family
being torn apart like this.
- You want to know
what's been going on?
I found out Dad's been lying to me
my whole life.
Unalaq told me everything--
how Dad and Tenzin
kept me trapped down here
while I trained,
how Dad got banished from the North.
- So the truth is out.
- You knew.
And you never said anything.
- We were trying to keep
our family together,
to give you a normal childhood.
- I never wanted a normal childhood.
All I ever wanted to be
was the Avatar,
but everyone keeps
holding me back,
even my own parents!
Unalaq's the only one
who believes in me.
- That's not true, Korra.
- No? Then why is everyone
in the South
turning against me,
when all I'm trying to do
is help them?
- The problems between the North
and the South
started long before you were born.
You can't expect to undo them in a day.
- So I should just sit back
and let the Water Tribes go to war?
- No, but this situation
might be out of your control.
Varrick's been plotting
a rebellion against Unalaq.
He asked your father to join, and--
- Dad is part of a rebellion?
- I don't know,
but I don't want you
getting caught in the middle of it.
- It's too late, Mom.
I'm already in the middle of it.
- Korra!
- Uncle!
Oh, no.
Uncle?
Dad?
- Dad, don't do this.
- Turn around, Avatar,
and pretend you didn't see anything.
- No. Leave Unalaq and go.
I'll tell him I tried
to stop you, but you escaped.
We can still avoid a war.
- No, we can't.
- Get him out of here!
We're all part of the same tribe.
I don't want to hurt you.
- Dad, stop!
- Why did you do this, Dad?
What? Who are you?
Where's my father?
- He wouldn't help us.
He's a traitor, just like you.
Thank you for saving my life.
- I'm just glad I got here in time.
- Find Varrick.
I want him to freeze in prison
with the rest of these traitors.
- Wait, you can't just lock them away.
That will only make the South angrier.
- You want them to go free?
- No,
but let them stand trial
for what they did.
Every Water Tribe citizen
deserves that right.
- Very well.
I will respect the Avatar's
wishes in this matter.
- Thank you, Uncle.
- I told you those rocks were slippery.
You're lucky you didn't kill yourself.
- You done with the lecture, Mom?
- Oh, grow up.
You haven't changed one bit
since we were kids.
You're still trying to prove
you can do everything a bender can.
Well, you can't.
Deal with it.
- And you're not our mother.
You don't get to tell me
what I can and can't do.
Deal with that. Ugh!
- Good luck healing yourself
with your special
non-bending powers.
- Hey, back me up here, Tenzin.
- Kya's right.
You're the oldest of us,
but you always acted like the youngest.
I had to become the responsible one.
- You think you're
the responsible one?
Where were you after Dad died
and Mom was all alone?
Because I was the only one
who packed up and moved
my whole life to be with her.
- Sure, after years
of flitting around the world,
trying to find yourself.
It was time for you
to settle down somewhere.
You two have no idea
how it feels to have the future
of an entire culture on your shoulders.
- Oh, boo-hoo.
Must've been real hard for you,
flying around the world with Dad,
riding elephant-koi all day.
- Oh, so that's what this
is all about.
- That's what
it's always been about.
You think you're some savior
who has to carry on Dad's legacy.
- Who else is going to do it?
- How about all of us?
- Yeah, we're Aang's kids too.
- We never should have come
on this vacation.
- I couldn't agree more.
- Well, I didn't want you
to come in the first place.
I can't be around you two right now.
Go back to the temple
and see if lkki returned.
I'll keep looking out here.
- Fine.
- Is it okay if I come in?
- Of course.
We heard what happened.
Are you okay?
- I'm so glad you weren't there.
I don't know what I would have done.
- I had no idea how far
Varrick was willing to go.
My brother and I
have our differences,
but I would never attack him.
- I'm sorry for thinking
you had anything to do
with the rebels,
and for all the pain
I've caused you and Mom.
- I'm the one who should apologize.
After I saw the southern lights return,
I was so proud of you.
I never should have held you back.
- When your father and I
found each other,
all we wanted was
to live a simple life
and raise a family.
But then we discovered
you were the Avatar,
and simple was over.
We knew one day
the world would need you,
and you wouldn't need us
anymore.
- Mom, Dad,
of course I still need you.
- We weren't expecting you.
- Tonraq, Senna,
you are under arrest
and will stand trial.
- Trial? For what?
- For conspiring to assassinate me.