- EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR...
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
[panpipes tag]
- TENSIONS BETWEEN THE NORTHERN
AND SOUTHERN WATER TRIBES
HAVE REACHED A BREAKING POINT.
AFTER CHIEF UNALAQ'S TROOPS
TOOK OVER THE SOUTH,
VARRICK INCITED AN UPRISING.
BUT KORRA STOPPED THE REBELS
FROM ABDUCTING HER UNCLE.
ENRAGED BY THE INSURRECTION,
UNALAQ ARRESTED THE REBELS
AND KORRA'S PARENTS,
ACCUSING THEM OF CONSPIRING
TO ASSASSINATE HIM.
WILL KORRA BE ABLE
TO SAVE HER PARENTS
AND PREVENT CIVIL WAR?
[wind whooshes]
[chains clinking]
[hinges creak]
[engine turns over]
- YOU'RE MAKING A MISTAKE.
- I WISH IT HADN'T COME TO THIS.
BUT YOUR PARENTS HELD MEETINGS
WITH THE REBELS,
RIGHT HERE IN THEIR HOME.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE DOING
THIS TO YOUR OWN FAMILY.
- REST ASSURED,
I'VE APPOINTED JUDGE HOTAH
TO OVERSEE THE TRIAL.
HE IS THE MOST FAIR
AND HONORABLE MAN I KNOW.
- UNCLE, MY PARENTS
HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE MEN
WHO ATTACKED YOU.
- I'M SURE YOU'RE RIGHT.
SO WE SHOULD HAVE NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
- I HOPE SO.
- WHERE'S VARRICK?
WE SHOULD'VE CLOSED OUR DEAL
AN HOUR AGO.
- WOULD YOU RELAX?
THIS PLACE IS GREAT.
AND THE BEST PART ABOUT IT?
ESKA DOESN'T KNOW I'M HERE.
[raccoon peeps,
door clangs]
- EE-YAH.
I WASN'T HIDING.
HEY, HEY-HEY, HEY.
- I'M NOT ON THE HUNT FOR YOU.
CURRENTLY.
- WE SEARCH FOR VARRICK.
OUR FATHER WISHES HIM
TO STAND TRIAL.
- WHAT DID HE DO?
- HE IS A TRAITOR
TO THE WATER TRIBE,
ALONG WITH OUR AUNT AND UNCLE.
- WHAT?
- KORRA'S PARENTS WERE ARRESTED?
- YES. YOUR POWERS OF DEDUCTION
ARE IMPRESSIVE.
- YEAH, HE'S A COP.
- VARRICK'S NOT HERE.
- VERY WELL.
DESNA, LET US CONTINUE
OUR SEARCH ELSEWHERE.
BOYFRIEND!
BOW TO ME WHEN I EXIT.
- YES, YES,
MY SWEET KOALA-OTTER.
- YOU ARE SO CUTE
WHEN YOU GROVEL.
[door shuts]
- DON'T LET HER TREAT YOU
THAT WAY.
STAND UP FOR YOURSELF.
- I TRIED TO BREAK UP WITH HER,
BUT MAKO GAVE ME
TERRIBLE ADVICE.
THANK YOU, MAKO.
- WAIT, HOW ARE YOUR GIRL
PROBLEMS MY FAULT?
- BOLIN, YOU NEED TO BE HONEST
WITH HER.
TELL HER HOW YOU REALLY FEEL.
- [muffled]
HONESTY IS FOR FOOLS, KID!
- VARRICK?
- [muffled] IF YOU WANT
TO DITCH THIS GIRL,
THEN MAKE YOURSELF SCARCE.
DISAPPEAR, LIKE I DID!
- WHERE ARE YOU?
- SOMEWHERE
UNALAQ WILL NEVER FIND ME.
INSIDE PING-PING!
HOW WE DOIN'?
- THE COAST IS CLEAR.
YOU CAN COME OUT.
- NO WAY, MISTER.
NOT UNTIL I KNOW
IT'S ABSOLUTELY, 157% SAFE.
AHH! THANK YOU, ZHU LI.
- YOUR ASSISTANT'S IN THERE TOO?
- ZHU LI NEVER LEAVES MY SIDE.
[slurps]
YUCK!
PYUGH! PYUCK!
YOU FORGOT THE HONEY!
- [muffled]
SORRY, SIR.
THERE ISN'T ANY IN HERE.
- NO HONEY?
WE'RE IN A BEAR,
FOR CRYING OUT LOUD!
- I'M GONNA GO SEE
HOW KORRA'S DOING.
- BOLIN, I GOT A LITTLE
SOMETHING FOR YOU 'ROUND BACK.
- WOW!
- NOW LISTEN UP.
UNALAQ'S RIGGED THIS TRIAL,
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
SO I NEED YOU TO MAKE SURE
MY TRUSTY REBELS
STAY OUT OF PRISON.
- WHAT'S THE MONEY FOR?
- [laughing]
BRIBERY, OF COURSE!
THERE'S ALWAYS SOMEONE WILLING
TO LOOK THE OTHER WAY
FOR A FEW YUANS.
- I THINK I CATCH YOUR DRIFT,
VARRICK-BEAR.
- IKKI!
IKKI, WHERE ARE YOU?
[animals purr]
- SHOO!
GO BOTHER SOMEONE ELSE.
YOU TWO ARE WORSE
THAN KYA AND BUMI.
- [shouting]
OKAY, EVERYBODY HERE?
- IKKI!
OH, THANK GOODNESS.
- JUNIPER LIGHTNING BUG,
PAWS OFF THE TABLE!
THIS IS GOING TO BE
A CIVILIZED BREAKFAST.
DADDY ALWAYS SAYS A BLESSING
BEFORE WE EAT, SO--
BE QUIET AND LISTEN UP!
[animals grunting]
WE ARE THANKFUL
FOR THIS SUPER YUMMY FOOD
AND FOR BEING THE BEST-EST
NEW FRIENDS IN THE WORLD.
BUT WE ARE MOST THANKFUL
BECAUSE MEELO AND JINORA
AREN'T HERE
BECAUSE THEY STINK.
[animals grunting]
OH!
HI, DADDY.
I GUESS YOU FOUND ME.
DO I HAVE TO GO NOW?
- ACTUALLY, IS THERE ROOM
FOR ONE MORE?
- UH, SURE.
YOU CAN SIT
NEXT TO BLUEBERRY SPICEHEAD.
- NICE TO MEET YOU,
BLUEBERRY SPICEHEAD.
- AND THAT'S PRINCESS RAINBOW,
AND THAT'S TWINKLE STARCHILD.
AND THAT'S
JUNIPER LIGHTNING BUG.
THEY'RE MY NEW BROTHERS
AND SISTERS.
- NEW ONES, HUH?
CAN THEY BE MY NEW BROTHERS
AND SISTERS TOO?
- MAYBE, BUT ONLY
IF THEY SAY IT'S OKAY.
UH-HUH, UH-HUH.
NO, NO, HE'S NICE.
THEY SAY IT'S OKAY.
[crowd murmuring]
- WE'RE GOOD TO GO. I GAVE ALL
THE MONEY TO SOME GUYS OVER
THERE.
I TOLD THEM
TO "TAKE CARE OF IT,"
AND THEN I WINKED.
[laughs] PRETTY SURE
THEY GOT THE MESSAGE.
[gavel bangs repeatedly]
- THIS TRIAL
WILL NOW COME TO ORDER!
JUDGE HOTAH PRESIDING.
- MAN! I SHOULD HAVE PAID HIM!
- YEAH, YOU THINK?
- I WAS ASLEEP IN MY CHAMBERS
WHEN THE REBELS ATTACKED.
THEY OVERPOWERED ME,
AND THE NEXT THING I REMEMBER
WAS WAKING UP IN THE SNOW
AFTER AVATAR KORRA HAD SAVED ME.
- ACCORDING
TO UNALAQ'S TESTIMONY,
YOU ATTENDED A MEETING
WHERE VARRICK TRIED TO INCITE
A CIVIL WAR.
IS THAT TRUE?
- YES.
- AND WERE THESE MEN PRESENT
AT THAT MEETING?
- WELL, YES, BUT--
- AND WHERE EXACTLY
DID THIS MEETING TAKE PLACE?
- OBJECTION!
- QUIET DOWN OUT THERE!
I'LL ASK YOU ONE MORE TIME.
WHERE DID THE MEETING HAPPEN?
- MY PARENTS' HOUSE.
- AND WHO LED THIS MEETING?
- YOUR HONOR, IF I MAY...
- MAY WHAT?
- MAY I...DECLARE A MISTRIAL?
- SIT DOWN.
VARRICK AND YOUR FATHER
LED THE MEETING, DIDN'T THEY?
- MY PARENTS ARE INNOCENT!
- I'VE HEARD ALL I NEED TO.
I'LL RETURN SHORTLY
WITH MY DECISION.
- HEY THERE, ESKA!
I WAS WONDERING
IF WE COULD TALK.
- I GRANT YOU PERMISSION
TO SPEAK FREELY.
- OH, GOOD, BECAUSE I JUST
NEED TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
YOU KNOW, WHEN WE FIRST MET,
THERE WAS THIS CRAZY SPARK.
BUT I'M STARTING TO FEEL
LIKE THAT SPARK IS FADING.
- I AGREE.
IT IS AS IF A GREAT CHASM
HAS FORMED BETWEEN US
AND NOTHING CAN BRIDGE IT.
- OH! OH, YES!
I AM SO GLAD YOU UNDERSTAND!
- NOTHING, THAT IS,
EXCEPT MARRIAGE.
[atmospheric boom]
[latch clacks]
- [grunts]
- WE WILL WED AT SUNSET.
YOU MAY EXPRESS YOUR JOY
THROUGH TEARS.
- [laugh-cries]
OH, NO, I CAN'T--
[coughing]
THIS IS REALLY TIGHT.
- SENNA, PLEASE STEP FORWARD.
I HAVE FOUND YOU INNOCENT.
YOU ARE FREE TO GO.
[chains clink]
- KORRA!
- ON THE CHARGE OF TREASON,
YOU ARE ALL FOUND GUILTY.
[crowd murmuring]
THE PUNISHMENT FOR THIS CRIME
IS DEATH.
- [gasps]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
YOU TAKE THEIR LIVES,
AND I'LL TAKE YOURS.
- KORRA, CALM DOWN.
I'LL TALK TO HIM.
I KNOW I PROMISED TO RESPECT
WHATEVER DECISION YOU MADE,
BUT I MUST ASK YOU
TO RECONSIDER.
SHOW THESE MEN
AND MY BROTHER MERCY.
- VERY WELL.
I'LL CHANGE THEIR PUNISHMENT.
YOUR LIVES WILL BE SPARED.
BUT YOU WILL LIVE THEM OUT
IN PRISON.
[chains jingling]
- THANK YOU, UNCLE.
[animals grunting]
- YOU LIKE THAT, DON'T YOU,
BLUEBERRY SPICEHEAD?
[cooing] YES, YOU DO.
[animal purrs]
YOU KNOW, I COULD GET
USED TO IT HERE.
NO ONE'S YELLING AT ME
OR TELLING ME I'M DELUSIONAL.
- WE SHOULD HAVE UNCLE BUMI
AND AUNT KYA COME VISIT.
I BET THEY'D LIKE IT TOO.
- LET'S NOT.
THEY'LL ONLY SPOIL
OUR GOOD MOOD.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
AUNT KYA IS SUPER NICE
AND PRETTY
AND ALWAYS ASKS ME
HOW I'M FEELING?
AND UNCLE BUMI IS, LIKE,
THE FUNNIEST PERSON
IN THE WORLD.
- BUT WHAT ABOUT MEELO?
HE'S HILARIOUS TOO.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT'S
GOING TO COME OUT OF HIS MOUTH.
AND JINORA CAN BE SO SWEET
AND GENTLE.
- AND MEAN.
AND BOSSY.
BEING PART OF A FAMILY
IS HARD, HUH, DADDY?
- I COULDN'T AGREE
WITH YOU MORE.
[distant animals grunting]
[animal grunts]
[animals grunting]
- BUT I GUESS THE NICE PART
ABOUT A FAMILY
IS THEY'LL ALWAYS BE THERE
FOR YOU.
EVEN THOUGH TWINKLE STARCHILD
AND PRINCESS RAINBOW FIGHT,
THEY STILL LOVE EACH OTHER.
- THAT'S VERY WISE OF YOU, IKKI.
- WE SHOULD PROBABLY
HEAD BACK, HUH?
- I SUPPOSE.
WE CAN'T HIDE
IN THIS CAVE FOREVER.
- DON'T WORRY, DADDY.
WE'LL COME BACK
AND VISIT BLUEBERRY SPICEHEAD.
I KNOW YOU REALLY BONDED
WITH HER.
- YES, I'D LIKE THAT.
- [sighs]
HONEY, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I'M FINE.
- GOOD, THEN LET'S BUST YOU
OUT OF HERE RIGHT NOW.
- KORRA, NO.
SAVING ME WOULD START A WAR.
IF FIGHTING WERE TO BREAK OUT,
THE NORTH WOULD CRUSH THE SOUTH.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
JUST PROMISE ME
YOU WON'T DO ANYTHING RASH.
- FINE.
I PROMISE.
[melancholy music]
♪ ♪
- [sobbing]
- IT'S OKAY, MOM.
- I-I HATE FEELING SO HELPLESS.
- I KNOW.
[tires screech]
[bang]
[tires screeching]
[thud]
OH!
[galloping]
[roars]
- OH!
[animal snarling]
[grunts]
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- IT'S NOT ABOUT WHAT I WANT.
IT'S ABOUT WHAT NAGA WANTS.
AND SHE'D LIKE YOU
TO LET MY FATHER OUT OF PRISON.
- I-I'M SORRY,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING I CAN DO.
I WAS JUST FOLLOWING
UNALAQ'S ORDERS.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- I-I'VE SAID TOO MUCH.
[animal growls]
[screams]
- UNLESS YOU WANNA BE
NAGA'S AFTERNOON SNACK,
YOU BETTER KEEP TALKING.
- I-I'VE WORKED FOR YOUR UNCLE
FOR YEARS!
HE SAID HE NEEDED EVERYONE
TO THINK THE TRIAL WAS FAIR.
- SO UNALAQ TOLD YOU
WHAT TO SAY?
- YES! EVERY WORD.
- THEN WHY DID HE HAVE YOU
FREE MY MOTHER
AND CHANGE YOUR SENTENCE?
- HE'S TRYING TO KEEP YOU
ON HIS SIDE.
BUT HE ALSO WANTS YOUR FATHER
OUT OF THE WAY.
JUST LIKE WHEN
HE GOT YOUR FATHER BANISHED.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN
"HE GOT MY FATHER BANISHED"?
[animal growls]
- NOTHING!
- KEEP TALKING.
- UH...
[forced joviality]
HEY THERE, DAD.
YOU'RE LOOKING WELL.
LOOK, UH, I'M SORRY
I DIDN'T TURN OUT TO BE
AN AIRBENDER LIKE YOU HOPED,
BUT I'VE TRIED MY BEST
TO KEEP THE WORLD SAFE.
HOPE I MADE YOU PROUD.
- OF COURSE HE'D BE PROUD
OF YOU, BUMI.
- KYA! I-I WAS JUST, UH...
CLEANING OFF DAD'S STATUE.
[coughs]
IT'S SO DUSTY IN HERE.
- COME HERE.
- THANKS, KYA.
YOU ALWAYS KNOW
WHEN I NEED A HUG.
- UNALAQ'S A LIAR AND A TRAITOR!
- I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO TELL YOU THAT
FROM THE GET-GO.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- I FOUND OUT THE TRUTH
ABOUT MY DAD'S BANISHMENT.
UNALAQ HIRED THE BARBARIANS
TO ATTACK THEIR TRIBE.
THEN HE TOLD THEM TO HIDE
IN THE SPIRIT FOREST,
KNOWING MY DAD
WOULD GO AFTER THEM.
- UNALAQ WANTED YOUR DAD
OUT OF THE WAY
SO HE COULD BECOME CHIEF.
IT WAS A SETUP.
- JUST LIKE THE WHOLE TRIAL.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I TRUSTED HIM.
I'M BUSTING MY FATHER
AND THE REBELS OUT OF JAIL.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
- IF YOU DO THIS,
THERE'S NO GOING BACK.
- I KNOW.
WILL YOU HELP ME OR NOT?
- OF COURSE, I'LL HELP.
- ME TOO.
- COUNT ME IN!
[door slams]
[hinges creaking]
- I DON'T EVEN WANT TO KNOW.
- SO I'M GUESSING THE BREAKUP
WITH ESKA DIDN'T GO WELL?
- NO, NO, THE HONESTY THING
WORKED OUT GREAT.
SO GREAT THAT SHE DECIDED
WE SHOULD GET MARRIED!
- SORRY.
- I'M PRETTY SURE
THE GUY
IS SUPPOSED TO GIVE THE GIRL
THE BETROTHAL NECKLACE.
- I GUESS ESKA
DIDN'T GET THE MEMO.
- LOOK, THE ONLY WAY
TO DEAL WITH CRAZY WOMEN
IS TO LIE BIG AND LEAVE FAST.
LUCKY FOR YOU,
VARRICK'S GOT YOUR BACK.
NOW GATHER 'ROUND PING-PING.
LET'S TALK PLAN.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[keys jingling]
[grating, sizzling]
- [screams]
[keys jingling]
- MY DAD'S IN THERE.
WHERE IS HE?
- I'M SORRY, KORRA.
YOU'LL NEVER SEE
YOUR FATHER AGAIN.
- WHERE'S MY FATHER?
- ON A SHIP HEADED
TO THE NORTHERN TRIBE.
HE'LL SERVE OUT
HIS SENTENCE THERE.
- BRING HIM BACK
OR I'M TAKING YOU OUT
AND THE REST OF YOUR ARMY.
- REMEMBER WHO YOU ARE.
AS THE AVATAR,
YOU CANNOT THREATEN WAR.
YOU MUST REMAIN NEUTRAL,
OR OUR TRIBES
WILL NEVER FIND UNITY.
- YOU DON'T WANT UNITY.
YOU WANT POWER.
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN JEALOUS
OF MY FATHER, HAVEN'T YOU?
YOU GOT HIM BANISHED
SO YOU COULD BECOME CHIEF,
AND I BET IT JUST KILLED YOU
TO LEARN HE WAS
THE AVATAR'S FATHER.
NO WONDER YOU KEPT TRYING
TO TAKE ME AWAY FROM HIM.
- ALL I'VE EVER WANTED IS TO
HELP YOU REALIZE YOUR DESTINY.
- WELL, I DON'T WANT YOUR HELP
ANYMORE.
- IF YOU START A WAR,
THE DARK SPIRITS
WILL ANNIHILATE THE SOUTH.
AND EVEN I WILL BE POWERLESS
TO STOP THEM.
- I'M DONE BEING MANIPULATED
BY YOU.
YOU'RE GOING TO BRING
MY FATHER BACK,
THEN YOU AND YOUR TROOPS
WILL RETURN TO THE NORTH.
- AND WHY WOULD I DO THAT?
- BECAUSE YOU STILL NEED ME
TO OPEN THE NORTHERN PORTAL.
- NO, I DON'T.
YOU'VE SERVED YOUR PURPOSE.
- AAH!
[liquid splashes]
- UH!
- IF WE GET TO VARRICK'S BOAT,
WE CAN STILL SAVE YOUR FATHER.
- LET'S GO.
[cheerful panpipes music]
♪ ♪
- YOU HAVE A LICENSE
FOR THAT ANIMAL?
- UH, YOU FELLAHS
SEEN A TRAVELING CIRCUS
COME THROUGH HERE?
- ZHU LI, DO THE THING.
- [breaks wind]
- THAT PLATYPUS-BEAR
IS POOPING MONEY!
[overlapping shouting]
[motor hums]
- WHERE'S YOUR DAD?
- ON A SHIP HEADED NORTH.
THINK WE CAN CATCH UP TO IT?
- SURE, ONCE YOU GET US PAST
OUR FRIENDS FROM THE NORTH.
- IF ONLY WE HAD A PLANE
TO GET ME CLOSE TO THOSE SHIPS.
I COULD WATERBEND THEM
OUT OF THE WAY.
- A PLANE? WELL,
WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO?
[bell ringing]
- UM, WHY DO YOU HAVE A PLANE
ON YOUR BOAT?
- IN CASE THE BOAT SINKS,
OF COURSE.
- BUT THERE'S NO RUNWAY.
HOW ARE WE SUPPOSED TO TAKE OFF?
- ZHU LI!
TAKE A NOTE.
BUILD RUNWAY.
- YES, SIR.
- I HAVE AN IDEA.
- NOW!
[men whining]
- CAPTAIN, YOU ARE NEVER
GONNA BELIEVE THIS.
[engine rumbling]
- THERE!
MY DAD'S ON THAT SHIP!
[airplane engine hums]
JUMP!
- WHOO-AH!
[men scream]
[glass clanks]
- [groaning]
- WHERE ARE THE PRISONERS?
- [whimpering]
- KORRA, THIS IS CRAZY.
YOU PROMISED ME
YOU WOULDN'T DO ANYTHING RASH.
- I HAD TO.
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
[gentle footfall]
- SWEETIE! YOU'RE OKAY!
OH! I WAS SO WORRIED!
DO YOU HAVE SOMETHING
YOU WANNA SAY TO YOUR SISTER?
- IKKI, I'M GLAD YOU'RE BACK.
- YEAH, SORRY
WE MADE FUN OF YOU.
- THANKS.
WANNA PLAY AIR BALL?
- SURE!
- YEAH!
- I WANTED TO APOLOGIZE
FOR HOW I ACTED YESTERDAY.
I'VE WORKED SO HARD
TO CELEBRATE DAD'S LEGACY
THAT I MAY HAVE OVERLOOKED
THE PARTS OF HIM
THAT WERE LESS THAN IDEAL.
- AND WE'RE SORRY FOR DUMPING
OUR FRUSTRATIONS WITH DAD
OUT ON YOU.
- YEAH, YOU DIDN'T DESERVE THAT.
- I THOUGHT YOU TWO
MIGHT WANNA SEE THIS.
MOM GAVE IT TO ME
BEFORE WE LEFT.
- THAT IS ONE
GOOD-LOOKING FAMILY, HUH?
- THAT'S ONE HAPPY FAMILY.
- SO ONCE I KNEW THE TRUTH,
I COULDN'T SIT BY
AND DO NOTHING.
- MY OWN BROTHER BETRAYED ME.
AND OUR ENTIRE TRIBE.
- WHAT'S OUR NEXT MOVE?
- I'VE BEEN RUNNING FROM MY PAST
FOR TOO LONG.
IT'S TIME TO PUT MY BROTHER
IN HIS PLACE.
- YOU HAVE OUR SUPPORT,
CHIEF TONRAQ.
- MINE TOO.
I'LL BE PROUD
TO FIGHT ALONGSIDE YOU, DAD.
- NO, KORRA.
- BUT YOU SAID THE SOUTH
DOESN'T STAND A CHANCE
AGAINST UNALAQ'S FORCES.
I CAN HELP.
- THE BEST WAY FOR YOU TO HELP
IS BY GETTING THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED REPUBLIC
ON OUR SIDE.
THE SOUTH CAN GIVE UNALAQ
A GOOD FIGHT FOR A WHILE.
BUT WE'LL NEED THE UNITED FORCES
IN ORDER TO WIN THIS WAR.
- ALL RIGHT, I'LL GET YOU
ALL THE HELP YOU NEED.
I LOVE YOU, DAD.
- I LOVE YOU TOO.
- I REALLY NEED TO THANK YOU,
KORRA.
- FOR WHAT?
I STARTED A CIVIL WAR.
- EXACTLY!
NOW ESKA AND I
ARE OFFICIALLY BROKEN UP.
- OH, LOOKS LIKE
WE HAVE COMPANY!
AND NOT THE FUN KIND!
- WHAT IS THAT?
[gasps]
[dramatic musical surge]
- THAT WOULD BE MY DARLING ESKA.
QUICK QUESTION:
IS THIS THING FAST ENOUGH TO GET
AWAY FROM MY CRAZY WATERBENDING
EX-GIRLFRIEND?
- WHY DO YOU THINK
I BUILT THIS BOAT?
[engine revving]