- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- IT'S BROTHER VERSUS BROTHER
IN THE WAR OF THE WATER TRIBES.
AFTER KORRA DISCOVERED
THAT CHIEF UNALAQ BETRAYED HER
AND HER FATHER,
SHE TURNED AGAINST HIM,
SPARKING CIVIL WAR.
THE SOUTHERN REBELS
RALLIED AROUND TONRAQ,
BUT THEY ARE
VASTLY OUTNUMBERED.
SO KORRA IS HEADED
TO REPUBLIC CITY TO SEEK AID.
BUT WILL SHE BE ABLE
TO CONVINCE PRESIDENT RAIKO
TO SEND TROOPS
TO HELP THE SOUTH?
- WELCOME HOME, AVATAR.
THANKS FOR STARTING A WAR.
- I DIDN'T START A WAR.
WELL, I DID,
BUT IT'S MORE COMPLICATED
THAN YOU'RE MAKING IT SEEM.
- MAKO, I WANT YOU
BACK ON THE BEAT.
THERE'S GOING TO BE A SOUTHERN
WATER TRIBE PEACE MARCH TONIGHT.
I NEED YOU THERE TO MAKE SURE
THINGS DON'T GET OUT OF HAND.
- I'M ALL YOURS.
- I'LL GO TOO.
THE PEOPLE
OF THE SOUTH NEED TO SEE
THAT THE AVATAR
IS ON THEIR SIDE
IN THE FIGHT
AGAINST THE NORTHERN INVADERS.
- GREAT.
THAT SHOULD CALM THEM DOWN.
- MAYBE YOU SHOULD SIT THIS OUT.
- WHAT?
- I JUST THINK HAVING YOU THERE
BLATANTLY SUPPORTING ONE SIDE
WILL ONLY MAKE THINGS WORSE.
YOU COULD AT LEAST
TRY TO SEEM NEUTRAL.
- I'M NOT NEUTRAL.
THE NORTH INVADED MY HOME.
THE ONLY REASON I'M HERE
IS TO GET THE REPUBLIC TO
SEND TROOPS TO HELP THE SOUTH.
- ZHU LI'S ALREADY SCHEDULED
A MEETING FOR US
WITH PRESIDENT RAIKO TOMORROW.
WE'LL GET HIM ON BOARD.
- WHATEVER.
I GOTTA GO TO WORK.
- I BETTER
GO CHECK ON MY FACTORY.
- I'M GOING TO FIND OUT
ABOUT THIS PEACE MARCH.
- AND I AM DYING
FOR A PEDICURE!
- SO, UH,
WHAT SHOULD I BE DOING?
- I DON'T KNOW, BOLIN.
FIGURE SOMETHING OUT.
- SAY, KID, HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
REPUBLIC CITY AT NIGHT?
[Pabu squeaks]
- SURE, I LIVE HERE.
- HAVE YOU REALLY SEEN IT?
- Y--NO?
- [chuckles]
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
COME ON.
- TONRAQ AND THE REBELS
ARE HOLED UP HERE
IN THE HILLS
OUTSIDE OF TOWN.
- LEAVE THEM.
MY BROTHER'S
NO THREAT TO US UP THERE.
INCREASE SECURITY
AROUND THE SPIRIT PORTAL.
KEEPING IT SAFE
IS OUR NUMBER ONE PRIORITY.
- YES, SIR.
[groans]
- I NEED YOU TWO
TO GO AFTER THE AVATAR.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN OPEN
THE NORTHERN SPIRIT PORTAL.
- BUT, FATHER,
YOU TOLD KORRA--
- I TOLD KORRA WHAT I THOUGHT
SHE NEEDED TO HEAR.
- I'LL FIND HER.
SHE STOLE MY HUSBAND.
- I NEED HER ALIVE.
- [sighs]
FINE.
[Poki chirps]
- WATCH ME, POKI.
YOU LAY DOWN AND ROLL OVER.
ROLL OVER.
- NO, NO, YOU CAN'T
JUST DEMONSTRATE IT.
THAT NEVER WORKS.
[Poki chirps]
- GOOD.
- UGH, CLASSIC OVER-REWARDING.
[bird screeches]
[Poki coos]
- POKI, WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- COMMAND RESPECT.
[grumbles]
[Poki chirps]
HAVING SOME TROUBLE, SON?
- POKI ISN'T
VERY GOOD AT LEARNING.
- BELIEVE ME,
I KNOW THE FEELING.
MAYBE I CAN HELP.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
YOUR OLD DAD
TO TEACH YOU
HOW TO BE A MASTER TRAINER?
- YEAH!
[indistinct chatter]
- TENSIONS ARE RUNNING HIGH
OUTSIDE OF THE SOUTHERN WATER
TRIBE CULTURAL CENTER.
THE AVATAR IS LEADING
A GROUP OF SOUTHERNERS
IN A PEACEFUL PROTEST
AGAINST CHIEF UNALAQ,
BUT THE NORTHERNERS
HAVE COME OUT IN DROVES
IN SUPPORT OF THEIR LEADER.
[angry crowd chatter]
- BOO!
- GET OUT OF HERE!
- GET A REAL JOB!
- YOU STINK!
[can crushes]
- HEY!
STOP!
REPUBLIC CITY POLICE.
[electrical humming]
- [grunts]
[tires screech]
- THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE
IS OUT OF CONTROL.
- I SAW A FIREBENDER
RUNNING AWAY FROM THE BLAST.
THE NORTH MIGHT NOT BE
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS.
- OF COURSE THEY'RE RESPONSIBLE.
[siren blares]
WHO ELSE WOULD IT BE?
[cheers and applause]
- WOW.
USUALLY, WHEN I SEE
FLASHING LIGHTS LIKE THIS,
IT'S BECAUSE I GOT HIT
IN THE HEAD WITH A ROCK.
- BEING FAMOUS IS LIKE
GETTING HIT WITH A ROCK
ALL THE TIME.
- LOOK!
IT'S BOLIN!
all:
BOLIN! BOLIN! BOLIN!
BOLIN! BOLIN!
- FOLKS,
THAT CHEER YOU'RE HEARING
IS FOR LOCAL FAVORITE, BOLIN,
OF THE FIRE FERRETS.
LET'S SEE
IF WE CAN GET A QUICK INTERVIEW.
BOLIN!
BOLIN, THE FIRE FERRETS
ARE OUT FOR THE SEASON.
HOW HAVE YOU BEEN SPENDING
YOUR TIME LATELY?
- WELL, I TOOK A TRIP SOUTH FOR
THE GLACIER SPIRITS FESTIVAL,
WAS BRIEFLY ENGAGED
TO A PRINCESS,
THEN WENT THROUGH KIND OF
A TOUGH BREAKUP THERE,
WAS ACCIDENTALLY INVOLVED
IN A CIVIL WAR...
- [coughs]
- BUT THERE'S
NOWHERE I'D RATHER BE
THAN PRO BENDING NIGHT
IN REPUBLIC CITY!
AM I RIGHT, PEOPLE?
REPUBLIC CITY!
[cheers and applause]
- DO YOU MISS
BEING IN THE RING?
- WELL,
I DEFINITELY DON'T MISS
GETTING HIT WITH THINGS
ALL THE TIME
AND THE HUMILIATING LOSING.
I MEAN,
THAT GETS PRETTY OLD.
YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES I ACTUALLY
CRY MYSELF TO SLEEP...
- [coughs]
- I GUESS WHAT I MISS THE MOST
ARE THESE FANS!
THEY'RE THE GREATEST FANS
IN THE WORLD!
GIVE IT UP FOR THE FANS!
[cheers and applause]
- LOOK HOW
THESE PEOPLE LOVE YOU, KID.
THEY'RE EATING THAT CORNBALL
SPIEL RIGHT OUT OF YOUR HAND.
- THE TRICK IS,
WHENEVER I GET CONFUSED,
I JUST SAY "REPUBLIC CITY"
OR "FANS,"
AND THEN EVERYONE CHEERS.
- I THINK I JUST FIGURED OUT
YOUR TRUE CALLING.
- I HOPE PRESIDENT RAIKO
LISTENS TO US.
- DON'T WORRY.
I WAS A BIG CONTRIBUTOR
TO HIS ELECTION CAMPAIGN.
HIM AND THE OTHER GUY.
GOTTA HEDGE YOUR BETS.
- HELLO, MR. PRESIDENT.
SIR,
THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE--
- JUST A SECOND.
KEEP SMILING.
- EH...
- NOW, HOW CAN I HELP THE AVATAR
AND MY MOST GENEROUS SUPPORTER?
- UNALAQ'S TROOPS
HAVE INVADED THE SOUTH.
WE NEED YOU TO SEND
THE UNITED FORCES TO HELP.
- I'M VERY CONCERNED
BY WHAT'S HAPPENING DOWN THERE,
BUT I DON'T THINK
IT'S THE REPUBLIC'S PLACE
TO INTERFERE WITH
INTERNAL WATER TRIBE MATTERS.
- UNALAQ ISN'T EVEN THE RIGHTFUL
RULER OF THE WATER TRIBE.
HE LIED HIS WAY
ONTO THE NORTHERN THRONE.
- MR. PRESIDENT,
THE REPUBLIC IS ALREADY
INVOLVED IN THIS CONFLICT.
THE NORTH ATTACKED
OUR CULTURAL CENTER LAST NIGHT.
- BELIEVE ME, WE ARE DOING
EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO BRING THE PEOPLE RESPONSIBLE
TO JUSTICE.
- "THE PEOPLE RESPONSIBLE"?
WHO ELSE WOULD IT BE
BUT THE NORTHERNERS?
- NOW, I KNOW
THAT WHEN YOU'RE YOUNG,
IT'S HARD
TO KEEP PERSPECTIVE--
- YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S LOST PERSPECTIVE.
I'M TRYING TO SAVE MY TRIBE,
AND YOU'RE TAKING PICTURES.
- SENDING TROOPS IS NOT
SOMETHING I CAN DO AT THIS TIME,
BUT I PROMISE I WILL WORK
WITH UNALAQ AND THE SOUTH
FOR A DIPLOMATIC SOLUTION.
NOW, I'M SORRY,
BUT MY MIND IS MADE UP.
THIS MEETING IS OVER.
- MY FAMILY
IS GOING TO BE WIPED OUT,
AND IT'LL BE ON YOUR HEAD
FOR DOING NOTHING ABOUT IT.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
THE PRESIDENT IS DOING NOTHING.
HE--HE DOESN'T EVEN CARE.
- I'M SURE HE CARES, BUT HE
CAN'T JUST TELL HIS PEOPLE
TO GO FIGHT A BATTLE
AT THE SOUTH POLE
THAT HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH THEM.
- HOW COULD YOU TAKE HIS SIDE?
- WHAT'S WITH YOU AND SIDES?
WHY DO YOU ALWAYS THINK
I'M WORKING AGAINST YOU?
- WELL,
YOU'RE NOT HELPING ME.
I'M TRYING TO GET TROOPS
TO THE SOUTH.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I'M DOING MY JOB.
- [laughs]
WELL, EXCUSE ME, OFFICER.
DON'T LET ME STAND IN THE WAY
OF YOU WRITING TICKETS.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO SAVE THE WORLD.
- WELL, YOU WOULDN'T HAVE TO IF
YOU DIDN'T KEEP MESSING IT UP.
- I CAN'T TALK TO YOU
WHEN YOU'RE LIKE THIS.
[door slams]
- [groans]
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S LIKE THIS!
[ship horn blows]
[footsteps]
- [gasps]
HEY, IN A HURRY?
- SORRY, I HAVE
TO TALK TO VARRICK.
- YEAH, ME TOO.
[bow fires]
[both gasp]
- OH, HELLO.
SEE?
I TOLD YOU I COULD DO IT.
- SORRY I EVER DOUBTED YOU.
- WE CAN'T WAIT
FOR THE PRESIDENT TO ACT.
WE NEED THOSE TROOPS NOW.
- AND MY COMPANY
IS ABOUT TO GO UNDER.
I HAVE TO FIND A WAY
TO MAKE SOME SALES.
- RIGHT. OKAY.
GOT IT.
IDEA STORM.
GET THE SUPPLIES.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO GET
AN INSIDE LOOK
AT HOW VARRICK GLOBAL INDUSTRIES
STAYS AT THE FOREFRONT
OF IMAGINATION INNOVATION
OR "IMAGIVATION"!
THAT'S TRADEMARKED, PAL.
BRAIN WORK REQUIRES
INCREASED CIRCULATION.
LET'S DO THIS!
OKAY, HERE COME THE IDEAS,
FAST AND FURIOUS.
PINK MINT LEMON TEA.
RADIO FOR PETS.
UH, HAND SHOES.
HOLD ON A TIC.
WE DON'T NEED THE PRESIDENT
TO GO TO THE SOUTH.
WE JUST NEED THE TROOPS.
LET'S GO STRAIGHT TO THEM.
IF THERE'S ONE THING
I KNOW ABOUT TROOPS,
IT'S THAT THEY LOVE FIGHTING.
- I KNOW GENERAL IROH.
HE MIGHT BE WILLING TO HELP US.
- A MAN ON THE INSIDE.
PERFECT.
AND YOU NEED TO SELL
SOME MECHA-TANKS.
I KNOW SOME PEOPLE
WHO NEED THEM.
WE'LL SHIP 'EM SOUTH.
- THAT'S PERFECT.
YOU'LL BE MAKING MONEY
FOR YOUR COMPANY,
AND YOU'LL BE HELPING
TO DEFEAT UNALAQ.
- IT'S TRUE.
IF YOU CAN'T MAKE MONEY
DURING A WAR,
YOU JUST FLAT-OUT
CANNOT MAKE MONEY.
- IT'S DANGEROUS
ON THE SEAS RIGHT NOW,
BUT I'M WILLING
TO TRY IF YOU ARE.
- IT'LL BE CRAZY RISKY,
BUT I LOVE CRAZY RISKY!
END STORM!
ZHU LI, GET THOSE OTHER IDEAS
TO RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT.
I WANT PROTOTYPES
BY NEXT WEEK.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY IT'S SO HARD
TO GET REPUBLIC CITY
TO SUPPORT THE SOUTH.
- DON'T WORRY.
I'M ALREADY WORKING ON THAT.
AS SOON AS PEOPLE SEE THIS,
THEY'LL BE LINING UP
TO FIGHT UNALAQ.
ZHU LI, DO THE, UH--
THE THING.
- DON'T FREAK OUT.
IT'S NOT REAL.
- I HAD A FILM CREW DOCUMENTING
THE ENTIRE NORTHERN INVASION.
- [screams]
[Pabu squeaks]
SORRY.
I KEEP DOING THAT.
- WE'RE GONNA CUT
THIS FOOTAGE TOGETHER
WITH SCENES WE SHOOT
OF OUR SUPERSTAR BOLIN HERE
PLAYING
A SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE HERO
BATTLING THE EVIL UNALAQ.
NO ONE WILL ROOT
FOR THE NORTH AFTER THEY SEE
THE ADVENTURES OF NUKTUK:
HERO OF THE SOUTH!
- I'M NUKTUK!
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
[door opens and closes]
OH, MAN, YOU SHOULD
HAVE SEEN VARRICK TODAY.
THAT GUY IS A GENIUS.
- UH-HUH.
- HE'S GONNA HELP ASAMI SELL
HER MECHA-TANKS TO THE SOUTH,
AND HE CAME UP
WITH THIS GREAT IDEA FOR KORRA
TO GET GENERAL IROH
TO FIGHT UNALAQ
WITHOUT PRESIDENT RAIKO
EVER EVEN KNOWING.
- WHAT?
THAT'S A TERRIBLE IDEA.
- AND HE'S GONNA
PUT ME IN THE MOVERS
AS THIS HERO, NUKTUK.
HE'S A MAN OF ACTION,
BUT HE'S GOT A HEART OF GOLD.
HE WAS BORN IN THE TUNDRA.
- LOOK, I'M TRYING
TO DO SOMETHING
THAT'S ACTUALLY IMPORTANT HERE.
- OH.
OH, SORRY.
UH, SURE.
WHAT IS IT?
- SOMETHING DOESN'T MAKE SENSE
ABOUT THIS BOMBING.
I JUST DON'T BUY
THAT THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE
WAS BEHIND IT.
WAIT A SECOND!
THAT'S HIM!
THAT'S THE GUY
THAT ATTACKED THE CENTER.
I GOTTA GO SHOW THIS
TO BEIFONG.
- GLAD I COULD HELP.
NUKTUK SAVES THE DAY AGAIN!
[Poki chirps]
- ALL RIGHT, MEELO.
THE FIRST THING
YOU NEED TO DO AS A TRAINER
IS ESTABLISH DOMINANCE.
YOU ARE IN CHARGE.
NEVER FORGET THAT.
NOW CALL POKI.
- POKI, COME HERE.
[Poki coos and scratches]
POKI.
[laughs]
POKI, NO.
- MEELO.
YOU'RE REWARDING HIM
FOR BAD BEHAVIOR.
- BUT HE'S TICKLING ME.
- YOU CAN'T LET HIM
NAP IN THE BED WITH YOU.
YOU ARE THE ALPHA LEMUR.
HE HAS TO SLEEP
ON THE FLOOR.
[Poki chirps]
I KNOW IT'S HARD,
BUT IT'S FOR THE BEST.
- NO, POKI.
THIS IS MY BED.
YOU SLEEP ON THE FLOOR.
[Poki whines]
BEING ALPHA LEMUR
IS LONELY.
- I KNOW.
- HOW DID THIS CULTURAL CENTER
ATTACK HAPPEN
RIGHT UNDER YOUR NOSE?
AND WHY HAVEN'T YOU ARRESTED
THE NORTHERNERS RESPONSIBLE?
- WE'RE WORKING ON IT, SIR.
- WELL, WORK HARDER.
IF YOU DON'T
GET ANY RESULTS SOON,
I'M GOING
TO FIND SOMEONE WHO CAN.
- I GOT A BREAK
IN THE BOMBING CASE.
I I.D.'D THE GUY
I SAW AT THE SCENE.
- THAT'S GREAT, MAKO.
- YEAH, YOU BETTER RUN THAT IN
TO BEIFONG RIGHT NOW.
- YOU THINK?
- SURE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE A HERO.
[knocks on door]
- WHAT MAKES
A ROOKIE BEAT COP
THINK HE CAN INTERRUPT
MY MEETING WITH THE PRESIDENT?
[both laugh]
- I'M SORRY.
I JUST--UM, I FOUND
SOMETHING OUT ABOUT THE BOMBING.
- WELL, GIVE IT TO LU AND GANG,
YOU MORON.
NOW GET OUT!
- SORRY.
WAS SHE BUSY?
- THIS IS THE GUY I SAW
SNEAKING OUT OF THE BUILDING
RIGHT BEFORE THE EXPLOSIONS.
HE'S A MEMBER
OF THE AGNI KAIS.
SOMEONE MUST HAVE HIRED HIM
TO MAKE IT LOOK
LIKE NORTHERNERS ATTACKED
THE CULTURAL CENTER.
- HMM.
- DID YOU LEARN ANYTHING
ABOUT THAT REMOTE CONTROL
I FOUND AT THE SCENE?
THAT'S GOTTA BE THE KEY
TO FINDING OUT
WHO'S REALLY RESPONSIBLE.
- LISTEN, KID, IT WAS
THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE, OKAY?
- YEAH, GIVE IT A REST,
SUPER COP.
[door opens and closes]
- I'VE HEARD GOOD THINGS
ABOUT YOU.
YOU'VE MADE SOME BIG TRIAD BUSTS
FOR A ROOKIE.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
- AND YOU'RE DATING
THE AVATAR, RIGHT?
- YES, SIR.
- I'M CONCERNED
THAT SHE MIGHT BE GETTING
SOME BAD ADVICE
FROM VARRICK.
YOU WOULDN'T HAPPEN TO KNOW
IF THEY'RE PLOTTING ANYTHING
THAT MIGHT COMPROMISE
THE SECURITY OF REPUBLIC CITY,
WOULD YOU, OFFICER?
LET ME REMIND YOU
THAT YOU'VE SWORN AN OATH.
YOU'RE A MAN OF THE LAW
BEFORE ANYTHING ELSE.
- YES, SIR.
- WELL, KEEP UP
THE GOOD WORK.
- [sighs]
WAIT.
THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU SHOULD KNOW.
- THANK YOU FOR SEEING ME,
GENERAL IROH.
- WHAT CAN I DO?
- THE SOUTH
NEEDS MILITARY SUPPORT
BEFORE UNALAQ
WIPES THEM OUT COMPLETELY,
BUT THE PRESIDENT IS REFUSING
TO GIVE THE ORDER.
SO I DECIDED
TO COME TO YOU DIRECTLY.
- I SEE.
WELL, SUPPOSE I WERE
TO TAKE THE FLEET SOUTH
ON SOME ROUTINE
TRAINING MANEUVERS.
AND LET'S SAY WE WERE
TO ACCIDENTALLY RUN
INTO A HOSTILE
NORTHERN BLOCKADE.
WE'D HAVE NO CHOICE BUT TO
DEFEND OURSELVES, WOULDN'T WE?
- I GUESS YOU WOULDN'T.
THANK YOU.
- SWAPPING OLD WAR STORIES?
- MR. PRESIDENT.
- I HOPE YOU'RE NOT PLANNING
TO TAKE ANY MILITARY ACTION
WITHOUT AN ORDER
FROM YOUR COMMANDER IN CHIEF.
- OF COURSE NOT, SIR.
- GOOD,
BECAUSE IF A SINGLE VESSEL
LEAVES THIS HARBOR
WITHOUT MY SAY-SO,
YOU'LL BE COURT-MARTIALED.
AM I CLEAR?
- CRYSTAL, SIR.
- YOUR ACTIVITIES HERE
ARE BORDERING ON INSURRECTION.
THE AVATAR DOES NOT COMMAND
THE MILITARY OF THE REPUBLIC.
DON'T GO
BEHIND MY BACK AGAIN.
AS YOU WERE,
GENERAL IROH.
- I HATE THAT GUY!
- I'M SORRY.
MY HANDS ARE OFFICIALLY TIED.
- I UNDERSTAND.
THANKS ANYWAY.
- BUT YOU SHOULD
TALK TO THE FIRE LORD.
MY MOTHER AND GRANDFATHER
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN GOOD FRIENDS
TO THE AVATAR
AND THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE.
I'M SURE
THEY'LL BE WILLING TO HELP.
- THANK YOU, GENERAL.
[upbeat music]
- WOULDN'T I BE COLD
WEARING THIS OUTFIT IN THE SNOW?
- AH, NUKTUK IS NEVER COLD.
- OOH.
HEY, GINGER.
- HOW ABOUT THAT, HUH?
IT'S THE LATEST PRODUCT IN
MY VARRI-MANAGEABLE HAIR LINE:
VARRI-DYE!
WE GET SOME SHOTS
OF HER USING IT
BEFORE UNALAQ KIDNAPS HER,
I GUARANTEE WE SELL
A MILLION CASES WEEK ONE.
- BOLIN, I NEED YOU TO WATCH
NAGA WHILE I'M GONE.
- WHERE YOU GOING?
- THE FIRE NATION.
I'M GOING TO TRY
TO GET THEM TO HELP THE SOUTH.
I NEED A BOAT.
- WHAT HAPPENED
WITH GENERAL IROH?
- HE WAS GOING TO HELP, BUT THEN
PRESIDENT RAIKO SHOWED UP.
SOMEONE MUST
HAVE TIPPED HIM OFF,
BUT I CAN'T FIGURE IT OUT.
NO ONE KNEW ABOUT IT
EXCEPT FOR US AND ASAMI.
- AND MAKO.
- MAKO?
- WHAT?
THERE'S NO WAY
MAKO WOULD HAVE TOLD.
RIGHT?
[Poki chirps]
- POKI, SIT.
[Poki squeaks]
ROLL OVER.
[Poki coos]
GOOD BOY.
- WELL DONE, MEELO.
I KNEW YOU COULD LEARN
TO TRAIN POKI.
- NOT JUST POKI.
I TRAINED
ALL THE LEMURS.
WATCH.
[blows whistle]
[lemurs squeaking]
[blows whistle repeatedly]
[blows whistle]
- I'VE CREATED A MONSTER.
UH, MAYBE WE SHOULD FORGET
ABOUT ALL THIS TRAINING
DISCIPLINE FOR NOW.
WHY DON'T YOU AND POKI
JUST HAVE FUN AND PLAY?
- THANKS, DAD.
TRAINING MAKES ME TIRED.
COME ON, POKI.
[blows whistle]
- YOU RATTED ME OUT
TO THE PRESIDENT?
- KORRA, LET ME EXPLAIN.
- EXPLAIN WHY MY BOYFRIEND
STABBED ME IN THE BACK?
- LOOK, THE PRESIDENT
OF THE REPUBLIC
ASKED ME
A DIRECT QUESTION.
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED TO DO?
- YOU BETRAYED ME
AND MY FAMILY!
[grunts]
- ENOUGH!
LOOK, I HAVE A JOB TO DO.
I CAN'T CONSTANTLY BE WORRYING
ABOUT KEEPING YOU
FROM MAKING
ANOTHER HUGE MISTAKE.
- WELL, I HAVE
A JOB TO DO TOO,
ONLY IT SEEMS LIKE YOU'RE
ALWAYS STANDING IN THE WAY
OF ME GETTING IT DONE!
- WELL, I GUESS IF WE'RE BOTH
PUTTING OUR JOBS FIRST,
MAYBE THERE'S NO ROOM
FOR OUR RELATIONSHIP!
- SO WHAT?
ARE YOU BREAKING UP WITH ME?
- YEAH.
I GUESS I AM.
- WHAT THE FLAMEY-O
HAPPENED HERE?
- I BROKE UP
WITH THE AVATAR.
- YOU GOT OFF EASY.
YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN
AIR TEMPLE ISLAND
AFTER TENZIN
BROKE UP WITH ME.
[motor hums]
[water splashing violently]
- [grunts]
- YOU RUINED MY WEDDING!
NO ONE STEALS MY BOLIN!
- [screams]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
[roaring]