- Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance
to the world.
- Someone has attacked
the Southern water tribe
cultural center.
All the evidence points
to northern sympathizers,
but mako suspects
there's more to this case.
Meanwhile,
varrick has cast bolin
as the hero
of his newest mover.
Asami has also ventured
into business with varrick,
and a shipment
of her mecha-tanks is on its way
to help the South
in its war against unalaq.
[Beeping]
- We're under attack!
Varrick is not gonna
be happy about this.
[Wind whistling]
- Where is he?
- Father said he would
meet us at this location.
He'll be here.
Were you just
in the spirit world?
- Never mind that.
Where is the avatar?
- She was within our grasp
until a dark spirit
attacked her.
- They're out of control.
- You didn't get her?
- The avatar is dead.
[Exciting music]
♪
- We finally made it.
Now we must stop
the evil unalaq!
[Crowd cheering]
- The Southern water tribe
is mine.
Next, I will conquer
the world
with my waterbending
doomsday device!
[Crowd jeering]
- Don't worry,
juji and roh-tan,
I will end the evil unalaq's
reign of terror.
For I am nuktuk,
hero of the South!
[Crowd cheers]
- Nuktuk, you're not just
the hero of the South,
you're our best friend.
Nuktuk-ity!
- You two are the best
snow raccoon and arctic panda
a guy could ask for.
All: Aww.
- ♪ Who's gonna fight
for friends and freedom? ♪
♪ nuktuk
♪ he's the biggest, baddest ♪
♪ bendingest man I know
♪ who protects the icy tundra?
Nuktuk ♪
♪ battling northies
out there in the snow ♪
♪ when unalaq starts trouble
♪ he'll punch him
in the mouth ♪
♪ he's nuktuk,
the hero of the South ♪
[Cheering]
- Bolin, look up there.
What do you see?
- I--
is this a trick question?
- I'll tell you what I see--
a star being born.
You're a star.
People love stars.
Stars tell them what to think
and how to act.
Bolin, have you ever
tried to force
a monkey-marmot
to ride a bicycle?
- Uh...Not that I can recall.
- Of course you haven't.
You can't force monkey-marmots
to do anything.
They've got to want
to do it themselves.
- Right.
- With these movers,
we'll have the support
of the people,
and before long,
they'll persuade the president
to lend his troops
to the war effort.
- [Sinister laugh]
My evil plan is working.
I've captured
nuktuk's beautiful girlfriend.
- Not so fast,
evil unalaq!
Oh, I will save
my true love and the South!
[Heroic music]
Both: Unh!
- And now,
your time is up.
[Dramatic music]
[Men grunting]
- It's no use fighting,
nuktuk.
My anti-energy net
makes bending impossible.
[Sinister laugh]
- No! Please.
Power...Weakening.
- Nuk-terrible.
- Will this be the end
of nuktuk?
Can he escape
from unalaq's trap
and save the beautiful ginger?
Find out next week
on the adventures of nuktuk:
Hero of the South.
[Cheers and applause]
- Wow. We got
some major chemistry on-screen.
Am I right?
- Yeah. On-screen.
[Scoffs]
- What's wrong?
Are you mad because I left you
in the clutches
of the evil unalaq?
I'm gonna save you
in the next episode.
Ginger,
let's work through this.
- Varrick, another one
of your ships has been captured.
- Darn it, zhu li,
haven't I told you
I hate getting bad news
without first getting good news?
- Oh, well,
the good news is
it looks like your first mover
has gotten a great reception.
- That's old news!
Let's go.
[Door opens]
- Is it true?
- I'm so sorry.
Your entire shipment was stolen.
- Without that sale,
I don't know how much longer
I can keep my company going.
What am I gonna do?
- Don't worry.
I'm gonna find
whoever's responsible.
Chief beifong
is about to question
the captain of the ship.
[Feedback hum]
- I know
it's been a long day,
but walk me
through what happened.
- We were ambushed about
30 klicks outside the harbor.
We never heard them coming.
- This is the third attack
this week.
At about the same location.
- Yep, and smack-dab
in Republic city's jurisdiction,
which means
another problem for us.
All this stress is gonna
turn old black beauty gray.
- It's gotta be
northern water tribe.
They're trying to stop
supply lines to the South.
- I agree.
Is there anything else
about the attack you remember?
Anything unusual?
- There is one thing.
The bombs exploded in a way
I've never seen before.
They didn't have fuses.
It was like they were
being detonated remotely.
- Like the bombs
at the cultural center.
- Wait,
where are you going?
- I gotta grab
some evidence.
- Asami, I heard the news.
I can't believe they took
my fifth favorite ship
in the varrick industries
fleet!
Named her after my mom.
Rest in peace,
rocky bottom.
- Without the money
from that shipment,
future industries is
almost broke.
- Chief, I think there's
a link between this attack
and the attack
at the cultural center.
- What do you think
you're doing?
- Solving this case.
Did any of the people
who attacked you
have one of these
in their hand?
I think
it's a remote detonator.
- It was too dark
to see anything.
- Mako!
- Chief, I don't think
the people who attacked
were northern water tribe.
- Of course they were
northern water tribe.
They were waterbending.
- Was this one of the guys
who attacked?
- No, I don't recognize him.
- Oh, that's embarrassing.
- [Chuckles]
Nice try, rookie.
- Mako, leave.
Now.
- Great work, everybody.
Another open and shut case
for the dynamic mustachioed duo!
- Wait, I think mako
might be onto something.
- Chief, I know
it's a long shot,
but I have an idea
how we can catch these guys.
- Yeah, let's all listen
to the rookie.
- He's doing a better job
than you.
- Who's hungry?
- Enough!
- [Clears throat]
- I don't want to hear
your lame-brained rookie ideas.
You're a beat cop,
not a detective.
Now hit the street
and do your job!
[Both laughing]
- Lu and gang are idiots.
I hate them
and their stupid mustaches.
- Forget them.
What's this idea of yours?
- A sting operation.
I was thinking
we'd set up a bait ship,
take it out
into the open ocean,
and capture
whoever attacks it.
- Let's do it.
- It's not that easy.
For the plan to work,
we need the police,
and beifong already
said no.
- We can make it work,
just the two of us.
- I don't know.
I don't want to go
behind beifong's back.
If she finds out, I could get
kicked off the force.
- Mako, I need your help.
My mom is gone.
My dad is in jail.
Future industries is all
I have left of my family.
- I want to help you,
but this is more
than a two-person job.
First of all,
we'd need a ship.
Both: Aah!
- You need a ship?
I got a ship.
I want in on
whatever you're talking about.
I love being in
on plans.
- The less you know,
the better.
- Perfect!
I love not knowing things.
- All right, I'm in.
Let's get these guys.
[Sea gulls squawking]
[Metal doors squeak]
- The ship's all loaded
with the dummy crates.
Let's get
this sting operation going.
- Not yet.
We need some extra manpower.
- What about korra?
No better muscle
than the avatar.
- Right, uh...Korra.
Yeah, actually, she's, um--
she's out of town right now.
- Everything okay
with you two?
- Yeah, yeah.
Forget about korra.
I'll go talk to bolin.
[Old-timey jazz music]
♪
- Hey, mako,
what do you think?
I did
a little redecorating.
It turns out that one
of the perks of being a star--
you get lots of cash.
- Is this a marble statue
of you?
- It's also a hat rack.
- We don't even have hats.
- That's because
we've never had a hat rack.
And now we do.
Mako, you seem stressed.
I think you need to take
a little dipity dip.
- I don't have time to take
a dipity dip, okay?
I'm trying to catch whoever's
been attacking the shipments,
and I need your help.
- You need my help?
[Groans] I don't know.
I'm kinda busy.
- You're sitting
in a hot tub.
- I'm maintaining
my instrument.
As an actor,
my body is my instrument.
- Are you gonna help or not?
- You know,
I recall a time
when I needed your help,
and you basically told me
to get a life.
- So that's a no.
What am I supposed
to do now?
- I don't know, mako.
Figure it out.
Remember?
That's what you said to me.
Hurts, doesn't it?
- [Grunts]
- [Screams]
Ow! My instrument!
[Dog barks in distance]
- Are you sure
this is a good idea?
- No, but it's
our last resort.
- Hey, mako.
Whatever you think we did,
we didn't do it.
- I'm not here
on police business.
I'm running
an off-the-books operation,
and I thought
the triple threats
might want a piece
of the action.
- How big a piece?
- So Mr. law and order
needs our help, huh?
What's in it
for the triple threats?
- I am personal friends
with the avatar.
I might be able
to convince her
to give shady shin
his bending back.
- Sounds good to me, boss.
- What about the rest
of us?
- I've got vehicles,
all brand-new
and top of the line.
They can be yours
if you help.
- I think we got ourselves
a deal.
- This is right around the area
where the attacks happened.
So keep your eyes peeled,
and stay quiet.
- I agree. Keep quiet,
mouth zipped, don't say a word.
That's the best thing to do
when you're trying
to ambush somebody,
which is what
we're doing here,
and it's basically
what I'm always doing.
I mean, I am a gangster,
after all, and--
- two toed ping, please.
- Oh, right.
So what's it like
dating the avatar?
- [Sighs]
- Come on, mako,
I gotta know.
- Ping, stay focused!
- What?
Why are you so weird about it?
If I was dating the avatar,
I'd tell you all about it.
- There's nothing to know.
I broke up with her.
- You broke up?
When?
Why didn't you tell me?
- I don't know.
- [Laughs]
Yeah, right.
You broke up
with the avatar.
Like that happened.
Hey, shady shin, viper.
Mako says he broke up
with the avatar.
- Sure he did.
- Yeah, I did too.
[Laughter]
- All right, would you guys
knock it off and do your job?
- And action!
- Forget about me.
You must capture
the evil unalaq
before he gets away.
- No!
I'll never leave you.
- Mm!
- Cut!
There's no kiss
in the script.
- Sorry, I just kinda
lost myself in the moment.
It just felt so right.
- Ugh!
- It did, huh?
Your girlfriend's about to die,
and instead of untying her,
you kiss her.
Wait a minute!
Maybe that will work.
Yes! It's genius!
Everybody take five.
Except for you, zhu li.
Grab the tweezers.
I've got some neck-hair issues
to resolve.
[Bell rings]
- So...That kiss.
I liked it.
And it seemed like
you liked it too.
- Ugh!
You're confusing ginger
the actress
with ginger the character.
- Okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm totally getting, like,
a weird vibe from you right now.
It's like, a minute ago,
when we were shooting,
you were into me,
but now you're not.
- That's because
ginger loves nuktuk,
not bolin.
- But nuktuk is bolin.
I'm a hero.
[Sighs]
- And that's why they call me
two toed ping.
- Because you have
two extra toes.
- That's right.
And there was already
a twelve toed ping
on the South side.
- Wait, guys.
Do you hear that?
- I didn't hear anything.
- No.
- Ah! What's taking so long?
- You just gotta relax,
like me.
Maybe try taking
your shoes off.
- I'm gonna check it out.
- So how long do we have
to stay out here?
- I told you,
it's gonna be a few hours.
What, do you have
a hot date?
- Actually, I do.
And I wanna look my best.
I gotta shower and shave.
I have a whole routine, okay?
- Well, your date's
gonna have to wait.
- She's not gonna be happy
about that.
- Too bad.
We were paid to keep mako
and that dame distracted
for a few hours,
so that's what we're gonna do.
- See, this is why
I never get dates.
- I just overheard
shady shin and viper.
We've been double-crossed.
We have to get off
this ship.
- Where do you think
you're going?
- [Grunts]
- Get 'em!
- [Shouts]
- [Grunts]
- [Screams]
- Aah!
[Dramatic music]
♪
They're getting closer.
- Not for long.
[Ship horn blares]
- Watch out!
We're not gonna make it.
All: Aah!
- One down, one to go.
Both: Oh!
[Engine stalls]
[Engine sputters]
- We're stalled.
- [Grunts]
- Unh!
- Uhh! Ooh!
[Engine starts]
- Mako, hang onto something.
- Unh!
- What was that all about?
- Someone paid the triple
threats to keep us distracted.
- Distracted?
From what?
Oh, no.
- Whoever paid the triple
threats stole everything.
- I'm ruined.
- My company...
It's over.
- We should check out
your other warehouses.
Maybe they didn't have time
to hit them all.
- You don't understand.
Everything I had
was in here.
- We have to search the place
for evidence.
If we can find a lead...
- Mako...
It doesn't matter anymore.
- I can figure this out.
- Just stop.
It's over.
I give up.
- Well,
I'm not giving up on you.
[Gasps]
- Sorry, I--
- uh...It's--
it's okay.
Um...Anyway...
I gotta run.
I'm gonna find out
who did this.
And I know just
who to ask.
- Hey, mako.
Uh, you're not mad
about last night, are you?
- Who hired you
to double-cross us?
- I don't know.
- I think you do know.
And you're gonna tell me,
or we're gonna have
to change your name
to "no toed ping."
- Really, I don't know.
You have to believe me.
We never met the guy
who hired us.
- [Chuckles]
You expect me to believe that?
- After you left the hideout,
some mook showed up
and said his boss would pay us
to keep you distracted.
We'd never seen him before,
and we ain't seen him since.
Come on, mako,
you know how these deals work.
Please.
I would never lie to you
with my lucky toes
on the line.
- Get out of here.
- [Panting]
- Bolin, have you seen
varrick around?
Bolin!
[Sighs]
Nuktuk.
- Yes?
Oh, hello, mako.
Didn't notice you there.
- [Sighs]
Where's varrick?
I need to ask him
something.
- Hmm. Can't say
that I've seen him.
But I've been kinda busy,
you know,
rehearsing for my big scene.
There's gonna be
some crazy "pyrotechnics."
That's mover speak
for explosions.
- We need nuktuk on set.
Running explosion scene.
- Or sometimes we just
call them explosions.
Anyway, wish I could
stand around here and chitchat,
but you know, I gotta go
shoot my big scene.
[Bell rings]
- Okay, the set is clear.
Camera's rolling.
And...Action!
- Ginger, stay down!
I'm coming for you.
[Running footsteps]
[Explosions]
- How did you rig
those explosions
to go off like that?
- Neat, huh?
It's a varrick industries
exclusive.
Here, check it out.
The explosions use
a remote detonator.
- Varrick.
Asami, I think I know
who set us up.
- Hello, mako.
- What are you doing here?
- He just saved
my company.
Varrick bought a controlling
interest in future industries.
Isn't that great?
- Yep, I like to think
I'm always there
to stand up
for the little guy.
Especially if that little guy
can help this guy
become a bigger guy.
- So what were you saying,
mako?
You think you know
who hired the triple threats?
- Yeah, and I'm real close
to proving it.
I'll fill you in later.
[Footsteps]
- [Grunts]
[Gasps]
Get away from me!
[Exhausted groans]
- It's okay, we're here
to help you, avatar korra.
- Who's--
who's avatar korra?
- What happened to you?
How did you end up
on our island?
- I...Don't know.
I can't remember anything.
[Sighs]
[Groans]