- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- THE AVATAR
HAS GONE MISSING.
AFTER PRESIDENT RAIKO
REFUSED KORRA'S REQUEST
TO AID THE SOUTH
IN THE WAR OF THE WATER TRIBES,
SHE HEADED
TO THE FIRE NATION,
SEEKING A NEW ALLY
AGAINST UNALAQ.
BUT UNBEKNOWNST
TO HER FRIENDS,
A DARK SPIRIT
ATTACKED KORRA
AND DRAGGED HER
INTO THE OCEAN.
SHE HAS WASHED UP
ON A DESOLATE ISLAND
WITH NO MEMORY
OF WHO SHE IS.
- WE FOUND THE AVATAR
WASHED UP ONSHORE,
BUT SHE DOESN'T
REMEMBER ANYTHING.
- [weakly]
RAAVA.
- A DARK ENERGY
HAS INFECTED HER.
WE MUST PURGE IT
BEFORE IT DESTROYS
HER AVATAR SPIRIT.
LET THE WATERS
CLEANSE THE DARKNESS
THAT PLAGUES
YOUR SPIRIT.
[ethereal music]
♪ ♪
- WHO ARE YOU?
- I AM YOU.
- WHO AM I?
- YOU ARE THE AVATAR.
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT IS.
- IN ORDER TO REMEMBER,
YOU MUST REGAIN
YOUR CONNECTION
WITH YOUR AVATAR SPIRIT.
- IF YOU DON'T,
DARKNESS WILL ENGULF THE WORLD.
YOU WILL DIE,
AND OUR ERA WILL END.
- HOW DO I REGAIN
MY CONNECTION?
- GO BACK.
RETURN TO THE BEGINNING.
FIND RAAVA.
- ARE YOU RAAVA?
- NO, BUT I CAN HELP YOU
FIND HER.
MY NAME IS WAN,
AND I WILL SHOW YOU
HOW I BECAME
THE FIRST AVATAR.
- NOBODY STEALS
FROM THE CHOU BROTHERS!
- REALLY?
BECAUSE I JUST DID.
- YOU'RE DEAD, WAN.
- ACTUALLY, I FEEL
QUITE ALIVE.
[Chous shouting]
[all grunt]
[birds screech]
- HEY, STOP!
[exciting music]
♪ ♪
- [laughs]
HEY, FELLAS.
YOU'RE JUST IN TIME
FOR LUNCH!
- OH!
[groans]
- [grunting]
- I TOLD YOU
NO ONE STEALS FROM US.
- [laughs nervously]
[shouts]
[groans]
[cow moos]
[snorts]
[groans]
- [sighs]
DID YOU STEAL
FROM THE CHOUS AGAIN?
- YEAH, AND I GOT NOTHING
TO SHOW FOR IT
EXCEPT A FEW DIRTY ROLLS
AND A WHOLE LOT OF BRUISES.
HEY, YAO,
I GOT SOME FOOD FOR YOU.
- MMM.
DELICIOUS.
THANK YOU, WAN.
[chirping]
- YOU GUYS ARE
HUNGRY TOO, HUH?
- WAN, YOU SHOULD EAT.
- [sighs]
THEY NEED IT MORE THAN I DO.
BESIDES, I'M TIRED
OF EATING SCRAPS.
IF ONLY THERE WAS
SOME WAY
TO GET
INTO THE CHOUS' FOOD CELLAR.
WE'D BE EATING LIKE--
WELL, LIKE CHOUS.
- IF CHOU THE ELDER CATCHES YOU
SNEAKING INTO HIS PALACE,
YOU'LL END UP DEAD.
OR WORSE, HE'LL BANISH YOU
TO THE SPIRIT WILDS.
- NO, DON'T GET BANISHED.
YOU DON'T WANT NOTHING TO DO
WITH THOSE SPIRITS.
THEY'LL GET INSIDE YA,
SCRAMBLE UP YOUR MIND,
TURN YA INTO THIS--
A MONSTER!
- DON'T DO
ANYTHING CRAZY, WAN.
YOU JUST GOTTA ACCEPT
THE WORLD IS THE WAY IT IS.
SOME PEOPLE HAVE POWER.
SOME PEOPLE DON'T.
AND YOU DON'T.
- [slurps]
NOT YET, ANYWAY.
- ARE YOU STRONG?
ARE YOU FEARLESS?
DO YOU HAVE WHAT IT TAKES
TO BATTLE THE SPIRITS?
THEN JOIN THE HUNT.
- COUNT ME IN.
- [laughs]
WE'RE GOING TO BE OUT
IN THE WILDS FOR A WEEK.
YOU WOULDN'T LAST
TWO SECONDS.
- I CAN HANDLE MYSELF.
WE ALL GET FIRE, RIGHT?
- YEAH, BUT DO YOU KNOW
HOW TO USE IT?
- WELL, NOT EXACTLY,
BUT I--
- AH, LET HIM COME.
NOT LIKE WE GOT
ANY OTHER VOLUNTEERS LINING UP.
- ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME TO THE HUNT.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[blows horn]
[rumbling]
- THE LION TURTLE.
- GREAT GUARDIAN
OF OUR CITY,
WE ARE VENTURING
INTO THE SPIRIT WILDS
TO BRING BACK FOOD
FOR OUR PEOPLE.
PLEASE, GRANT US
THE POWER OF FIRE.
- THE POWER IS YOURS
TO KEEP
UNTIL YOUR RETURN.
- YOU'RE FIRST, KID.
- MAY THE ELEMENT
OF FIRE
PROTECT YOU
AGAINST THE SPIRITS.
- WHOA!
[groans]
- JUST MAKE SURE YOU AIM
AT THE SPIRITS, NOT US, OKAY?
- SURE THING.
- EVERYONE STAY CLOSE.
SPIRITS LOVE
TO PICK OFF STRAGGLERS.
- UH, GUYS?
I DON'T THINK
I CAN DO THIS.
- NOW, QUIT YOUR WHINING.
WE HAVEN'T EVEN SEEN
A SPIRIT YET.
- I THINK
I WANNA GO HOME.
- I KNEW YOU WERE NOTHING
BUT A SNIVELING COWARD.
GO GIVE YOUR FIRE BACK
TO THE LION TURTLE,
AND DON'T EVER SHOW
YOUR FACE AROUND ME AGAIN.
- WAN, YOU'RE BACK.
- WHAT GOODIES DID YOU SNATCH
FOR US THIS TIME?
- [gasps]
- [screams]
- WHAT DID YOU DO?
YOU CAN'T STEAL
FROM THE LION TURTLE.
- REALLY?
BECAUSE I JUST DID.
- YOU KNOW
IT'S FORBIDDEN
TO BRING THE POWER
OF THE ELEMENT INTO THE CITY.
PLEASE, GO BACK
TO THE LION TURTLE
AND RETURN THE FIRE.
- JAYA, IT'S TIME TO STOP
BEING SO AFRAID OF THE CHOUS
AND SHOW THEM WE HAVE THE POWER
TO CHANGE THINGS.
HEY, CHOUS!
OPEN THE GATE, AND LET US IN.
- WHAT ARE THOSE FILTHY PEASANTS
DOING HERE?
- DON'T WORRY, FATHER.
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF THEM.
[door slides open]
- HAND OVER ALL THE FOOD
YOU'RE HOARDING,
AND WE WON'T GIVE YOU
ANY TROUBLE.
[Chous laugh]
- YOU'RE NOT GETTING
PAST US.
WE HAVE THE WEAPONS.
YOU'RE POWERLESS.
- POWERLESS, HUH?
[Chous groaning]
FOLLOW ME!
GRAB AS MUCH FOOD
AS YOU CAN.
- MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT.
MAYBE WE DO HAVE THE POWER
TO CHANGE THINGS.
- STOP RIGHT THERE!
- LOOKS LIKE THE CHOUS
FOUND BACKUP.
- GET EVERYONE
OUT OF HERE.
I'LL HOLD THEM OFF.
[all grunting]
- NO, PLEASE.
HAVE MERCY.
WAN?
- [groans]
- EVEN WHEN YOU HAVE THE POWER,
YOU'RE AFRAID TO USE IT.
- TELL ME WHO ELSE
WAS INVOLVED IN THE REBELLION,
AND I MIGHT TAKE MERCY
ON YOU.
- I'M NOT
TELLING YOU ANYTHING.
- THEN, YOU'VE LEFT ME
NO CHOICE.
WAN, YOU ARE
HEREBY BANISHED.
- YEAH! AND GIVE BACK
THE FIRE YOU STOLE.
- NO!
WAIT.
GREAT LION TURTLE,
I AM SORRY
FOR STEALING THE FIRE FROM YOU,
AND I ACCEPT MY PUNISHMENT.
BUT PLEASE,
I NEED TO BE ABLE
TO PROTECT MYSELF
IN THE WILDS.
- NEVER AGAIN
MAY YOU RETURN
TO THIS CITY.
BUT I WILL ALLOW YOU
TO KEEP
THE POWER OF THE ELEMENT.
- [grunts]
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- BET HE DOESN'T LAST
TILL MORNING.
[howling, chirping]
- HEY, WATCH WHERE
YOU'RE STEPPING, HUMAN!
- WHO SAID THAT?
- DOWN HERE!
HOW'D YOU LIKE IT IF I STARTED
WALKING ALL OVER YOU?
- [sighs]
YOU'RE JUST A LITTLE FROG.
[shouts]
- WHO'S LITTLE NOW?
- [gasps]
[grunting]
[shouts]
- [belches]
- [panting]
[panting]
[ominous music]
[muffled groaning]
[panting]
[stomach growls]
[sighs]
GET OFF ME!
[screams]
[groans]
[shouts]
[mystical music]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
- YOU ARE NOT WELCOME
IN MY OASIS, HUMAN.
- PLEASE, HELP ME.
I'M STARVING,
AND I HAVEN'T SLEPT ALL NIGHT.
- NOT MY PROBLEM.
- LET ME PASS.
- YOU DARE USE FIRE
AGAINST ME?
NOW, BE GONE WITH YOU!
- [groans]
[sighs]
[mystical music]
[gasps]
♪ ♪
[spirits chirping]
- AND WHO MIGHT YOU BE?
- I AM BUSHY,
THE BUSH SPIRIT.
AND I WOULD LIKE TO ENTER
YOUR OASIS.
- VERY WELL.
YOU MAY PASS.
[sniffs]
WAIT A SECOND!
SOMETHING STINKS.
I KNEW I SMELLED
A HUMAN!
- [sighs]
[groans]
COME ON, LET ME IN,
JUST FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
- NO!
GO BACK TO YOUR LION TURTLE.
- BELIEVE ME,
I'D LOVE TO GO BACK HOME.
BUT I CAN'T.
I WAS KICKED OUT.
- THAT'S TOO BAD.
- POOR HUMAN.
- DON'T PITY HIM.
HE'S JUST LIKE
EVERY OTHER HUMAN:
UGLY, DESTRUCTIVE,
AND LACKING ANY RESPECT
FOR NATURE.
- WHO ARE YOU CALLING UGLY,
UGLY?
- HMM.
- IF YOU CAN'T GO BACK
TO YOUR CITY,
THEN YOU SHOULD GO LIVE
IN ANOTHER ONE.
- WHAT?
THERE ARE OTHER LION TURTLES?
- "THERE ARE
OTHER LION TURTLES?"
OF COURSE THERE ARE,
DOZENS OF THEM!
BOY, YOU HUMANS
ARE STUPID TOO.
- SO WHICH WAY
TO THE NEAREST LION TURTLE CITY?
- HMM.
I THINK
IT'S ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF NONE-OF-YOUR-BUSINESS VALLEY.
[laughs]
[sighs]
- REAL FUNNY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T NEED YOUR HELP.
I'LL FIND IT MYSELF.
- GOOD LUCK!
[gentle music]
♪ ♪
[stomach growls]
[cat-deer growls]
[cat-deer whimpers]
- [sighs]
[cat-deer growls]
IT'S OKAY.
I'M GONNA GET YOU OUT OF THERE.
- FINALLY,
WE CAUGHT SOMETHING.
GET IT DOWN.
- BACK OFF.
- WAN?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M SAVING
THIS ANIMAL.
- THAT ANIMAL'S
OUR DINNER.
NOW, GET OUT
OF THE WAY.
- NO.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- AHH!
HE--HELP!
HELP!
- GET 'EM OFF!
GET 'EM OFF!
AHH!
- [shouts]
[groans]
- WELL, LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE ALL OUT OF TRICKS, WAN.
- I REALLY HATE HUMANS!
- NO, NO.
[screams]
- [groans]
[sighs]
[screams]
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HE'S SCREAMING ABOUT.
HE'S BETTER-LOOKING NOW.
- I FEEL GREAT.
WHAT'S IN THIS WATER?
- IT HAS
SPECIAL HEALING PROPERTIES.
- THANKS.
SO WHAT DID YOU DO
TO THAT HUNTER?
- SPIRITS ARE ABLE
TO TAKE OVER
A HUMAN BODY
FOR A SHORT TIME.
IF I STAYED IN THERE
ANY LONGER,
I WOULD'VE KILLED HIM,
WHICH I DID CONSIDER.
- THANKS FOR SAVING
MY NECK.
BUT WHY'D YOU DO IT?
- I SAW YOU SAVE THE CAT-DEER
FROM THOSE HUNTERS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
SUCH AN ACT
OF SELFLESSNESS
FROM A HUMAN BEFORE.
- TOLD YOU
I WASN'T LIKE THE OTHERS.
- GUESS I UNDERESTIMATED YOU,
HUMAN.
- ARE YOU OFF TO FIND
ANOTHER LION TURTLE CITY?
- I WAS.
BUT I THINK I'VE HAD ENOUGH
OF HUMANS FOR A WHILE.
I'VE DECIDED
TO STAY HERE
AND LEARN THE WAYS
OF THE SPIRITS.
- WHAT A GREAT IDEA.
- THAT'LL BE FUN.
- OH, NOW, NOW,
HOLD ON.
A HUMAN LIVING
WITH SPIRITS?
IT'S NEVER BEEN DONE.
- FIRST TIME
FOR EVERYTHING, RIGHT?
- HMM.
I GUESS
WE CAN TRY IT.
I'VE NEVER HAD A HUMAN
AS A PET BEFORE.
I THINK
I'LL CALL YOU "STINKY."
- THE NAME IS WAN.
- STINKY IS
MORE ACCURATE.
- WHAT HAPPENED
IN THE WILDS?
WHERE ARE THE OTHERS?
- GONE.
SPIRITS TOOK THEM.
THEY WERE PROTECTING
THAT KID WAN
LIKE HE WAS
ONE OF THEIR OWN.
- DID YOU HEAR THAT?
WAN'S STILL ALIVE.
- [growls]
[applause]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- AND THE WAY WAN
MOVES FIRE,
IT'S LIKE NOTHING
I'VE EVER SEEN.
HE USES IT LIKE
IT'S AN EXTENSION OF HIS BODY.
[groaning]
[all cheering]
- WAN HAS PROVEN
THAT WITH THE POWER OF FIRE,
ANYONE CAN SURVIVE
IN THE WILDS.
WE DON'T HAVE TO LIVE
UNDER CHOU THE ELDER'S RULES
ANYMORE,
SO I SAY WE LEAVE THIS CITY
AND START OVER.
WHO'S WITH ME?
[all cheering]
[gentle music]
♪ ♪
- YOU READY TO GO, MULA?
- YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO LEAVE?
- YES, IT'S TIME I SEE
THE REST OF THE WORLD
AND FIND
THE OTHER LION TURTLE CITIES.
- I'M PROUD TO CALL YOU
MY FRIEND, STINKY.
- [sighs]
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING.
GOOD-BYE, EVERYONE.
- WE'LL MISS YOU.
♪ ♪
- [whimpers]
- [groans]
- THE ALL-POWERFUL SPIRITS
ARE BATTLING.
- THEY'RE GONNA WIPE OUT
THE ENTIRE VALLEY!
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[Mula growls]
[spirits grunting]
- STOP,
OR YOU'LL DESTROY EVERYTHING!
- THIS DOESN'T
CONCERN YOU, HUMAN!
- IT DOES
WHEN THE LIVES
OF SPIRITS AND ANIMALS
ARE IN DANGER.
- IF YOU'RE A FRIEND
TO SPIRITS,
THEN USE YOUR FIRE TO HELP ME
BREAK FREE.
- DON'T INVOLVE THE HUMAN.
THIS IS BETWEEN US.
- PLEASE, SAVE ME.
SHE HAS TORMENTED ME
FOR 10,000 YEARS.
- 10,000 YEARS?
LET HIM GO!
[shouts]
- [screams]
- THANK YOU, HUMAN.
YOU HAVE PERFORMED
A GREAT SERVICE FOR THE SPIRITS.
- DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT YOU'VE DONE?
- YEAH, I HELPED A SPIRIT
WHO WAS BEING BULLIED BY YOU.
- YOU ARE
GRAVELY MISTAKEN.
I WAS KEEPING HIM
UNDER CONTROL.
- AND WHAT GIVES YOU
THE RIGHT?
- YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW WHO I AM,
DO YOU?
- SHOULD I?
- YES.
MY NAME IS RAAVA.
THAT SPIRIT YOU FREED
IS VAATU.
HE IS THE FORCE
OF DARKNESS AND CHAOS.
I AM THE FORCE
OF LIGHT AND PEACE.
SINCE THE BEGINNING
OF TIME,
WE HAVE BATTLED
OVER THE FATE OF THIS WORLD.
AND FOR THE PAST
10,000 YEARS,
I HAVE KEPT DARKNESS
UNDER CONTROL
AND THE WORLD
IN BALANCE,
UNTIL YOU CAME ALONG.
- SO BY FREEING VAATU,
I LET CHAOS
INTO THE WORLD?
- PRECISELY.
THE HUMAN
AND SPIRIT REALMS
ARE HEADED
TOWARD ANNIHILATION,
AND IT'S ALL YOUR FAULT.
- RAAVA, I FOUND YOU.