- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- AVATAR KORRA
HAS LOST HER MEMORY!
IN ORDER TO RESTORE IT,
SHE HAS CONNECTED WITH WAN,
WHO WOULD BECOME
THE VERY FIRST AVATAR.
BANISHED FROM HIS HOME,
WAN SURVIVED
FOR TWO YEARS
IN THE SPIRIT WILDS
AND LEARNED
TO MASTER FIRE.
BUT THEN,
WAN SPLIT THE SPIRITS
OF LIGHT AND DARK,
RAAVA AND VAATU,
UNWITTINGLY PLUNGING THE WORLD
TOWARD ANNIHILATION.
WILL HE BE ABLE TO STOP IT?
- SHOULD WE PULL HER UP?
- NO.
SHE IS CONNECTING WITH
HER DEEPEST AVATAR MEMORIES.
SHE MUST CONFRONT
HER OWN PAST
IF SHE IS
TO MOVE FORWARD.
WE CAN ONLY HOPE
THAT SHE SURVIVES HER ORDEAL.
- THE HUMAN AND SPIRIT REALMS
ARE HEADED
TOWARD ANNIHILATION.
AND IT'S ALL YOUR FAULT.
THIS IS WHY
HUMANS HAVE NO PLACE
INTERFERING IN THE BUSINESS
OF SPIRITS.
- THIS WORLD IS HOME
TO ALL OF US,
AND WHAT HAPPENS HERE IS
EVERYONE'S BUSINESS.
- THANKS TO YOU,
THIS WORLD MAY CEASE
TO EXIST!
I ONLY HOPE
I CAN TRACK DOWN VAATU
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
- LET ME HELP YOU.
- I DON'T WANT YOUR HELP.
DON'T INTERFERE WITH ME
AGAIN, HUMAN!
- LET'S GET MOVING.
[Mula growls]
DO YOU SEE THAT, MULA?
PEOPLE.
AND THEY HAVE SOME KIND
OF WIND POWER.
[Mula growls]
[laughs]
MORE HUMANS!
I FOUND YOU.
- AAH!
- WAIT! I'M FRIENDLY!
[shouts]
[breathing heavily]
[grunting, panting]
HUH?
[birds chirping]
THE LEGENDS ARE TRUE.
ANOTHER LION TURTLE CITY.
AND IT'S FLYING.
I HAVE GOT TO GET OVER THERE.
THERE.
OKAY, MULA.
WISH ME LUCK.
[screams]
OH, NO--
[panting]
WOW.
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
I'M WAN.
I'M SORRY TO INTERRUPT,
BUT IT'S BEEN A WHILE
SINCE I'VE SEEN OTHER HUMANS.
- WHERE DID YOU COME FROM,
STRANGER?
- ANOTHER LION TURTLE CITY
FAR AWAY.
FOR THE PAST TWO YEARS I'VE
BEEN LIVING AMONG THE SPIRITS
AND EXPLORING THE WILDS.
- REMARKABLE.
COME. SIT WITH US.
WE WOULD LOVE TO HEAR
OF YOUR TRAVELS.
- [gasps]
[both screaming]
[laughter]
- [exclaims]
- [shouting]
[all yelling]
- VAATU.
- SO WE MEET AGAIN, HUMAN.
- WHY IS THE GREAT SPIRIT
OF DARKNESS HERE
BUT NOT HIS OTHER HALF?
- UH, I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
LEAVE THESE PEOPLE IN PEACE.
THEY'VE DONE NOTHING
TO HARM YOU.
- [gasps]
[whimpers]
- BE GONE.
[crash]
- HOW ARE YOU FEELING
SINCE OUR SPLIT, RAAVA?
I'VE NEVER BEEN BETTER.
WHEN HARMONIC CONVERGENCE COMES,
I WILL DESTROY YOU FOREVER.
- [sighs]
- I TOLD YOU NOT TO INTERFERE.
- I HAD TO DO SOMETHING.
THESE PEOPLE WERE IN DANGER.
- GREAT SPIRIT OF LIGHT,
WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
BUT HOW DID YOU BECOME SPLIT
FROM VAATU?
- ASK HIM.
- IT WASN'T MY FAULT.
VAATU TRICKED ME
INTO FREEING HIM.
I'D TAKE IT ALL BACK
IF I COULD.
- IT'S TOO LATE FOR THAT.
NOW THAT VAATU IS FREE,
HE IS TURNING
OTHER SPIRITS DARK.
THE MORE SPIRITS HE TURNS,
THE STRONGER HE BECOMES.
- HE'S GETTING BIGGER,
AND YOU'RE GETTING SMALLER.
- AS DARKNESS GROWS,
LIGHT FADES.
- I'M SORRY FOR ENDANGERING
YOUR VILLAGE,
BUT I PROMISE
TO SET THINGS RIGHT.
- HOW?
- GREAT LION TURTLE,
I ASK THAT YOU GRANT ME
THE POWER OF AIR
SO THAT I CAN DEFEAT VAATU
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
- YOU ALREADY CARRY
THE POWER OF FIRE.
NO HUMAN HAS EVER HELD
TWO ELEMENTS AT THE SAME TIME.
- I'M NOT LIKE OTHER HUMANS.
I CAN LEARN TO DO IT.
- HMM, PERHAPS.
BUT TO DO SO, RAAVA
MUST HOLD THE POWER FOR YOU
UNTIL YOU MASTER IT.
- ANCIENT ONE, WHY WOULD I
DO THAT FOR A HUMAN?
ESPECIALLY ONE WHO'S CAUSED
SO MUCH TROUBLE?
- RAAVA, PLEASE, I CAN'T LET
THE WORLD FALL INTO CHAOS
BECAUSE OF MY MISTAKE.
NEITHER OF US
CAN DEFEAT VAATU ALONE,
BUT TOGETHER WE HAVE A CHANCE.
- YOU MAY BE RIGHT.
VERY WELL.
I WILL HELP YOU TO MASTER
THE POWER OF AIR.
- THANK YOU.
AND IN RETURN I WILL HELP YOU
RESTORE BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- WHAT'S THIS HARMONIC THING
VAATU WAS TALKING ABOUT?
- HARMONIC CONVERGENCE.
THAT IS WHEN VAATU AND I
MUST BATTLE
FOR THE FATE OF THE WORLD.
- HOW LONG DO WE HAVE
UNTIL THEN?
- ABOUT A YEAR
IN YOUR TIME.
- THEN WE BETTER START TRAINING.
ALL RIGHT,
I'M READY TO TRY AIR.
HOW'S THIS GONNA WORK?
- THE ONLY WAY FOR ME
TO GIVE YOU
THE OTHER ELEMENT
IS TO PASS
THROUGH YOUR BODY
AND COMBINE OUR ENERGIES.
- GREAT.
SO YOU'VE DONE THIS BEFORE.
- NO. THIS HAS NEVER
EVEN BEEN ATTEMPTED.
IT IS VERY DANGEROUS.
- THAT'S WHAT THEY SAID ABOUT
LIVING IN THE SPIRIT WILDS,
AND I SURVIVED THAT.
I'M READY.
GIVE ME THE AIR.
[shouts]
IT FEELS COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
IF YOU AND VAATU HAVE THE SAME
FIGHT EVERY 10,000 YEARS,
WHY HASN'T ONE OF YOU
DESTROYED THE OTHER?
- HE CANNOT DESTROY LIGHT
ANY MORE
THAN I CAN DESTROY DARKNESS.
ONE CANNOT EXIST
WITHOUT THE OTHER.
EVEN IF I DEFEAT VAATU
IN THIS ENCOUNTER,
DARKNESS WILL GROW INSIDE ME
UNTIL HE EMERGES AGAIN.
THE SAME WILL HOLD TRUE
IF VAATU DEFEATS ME.
- THAT DOESN'T SOUND SO BAD.
EVEN IF VAATU WINS,
YOU'LL COME BACK.
- YES, BUT YOU WILL
PROBABLY NOT SURVIVE TO SEE IT.
VAATU WILL DESTROY THE WORLD
AS YOU KNOW IT.
DARKNESS WILL COVER THE EARTH
FOR 10,000 YEARS.
- IF I'M GONNA HELP YOU
BATTLE VAATU,
THEN I SHOULD VISIT
MORE LION TURTLES.
WHY IS THERE SO MUCH CONFLICT
BETWEEN HUMANS AND SPIRITS
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
- THIS PHYSICAL WORLD
IS WHERE HUMANS COME FROM.
SPIRITS COME FROM ANOTHER REALM.
AT THE NORTH AND SOUTH POLES,
THE TWO REALMS INTERSECT.
OVER TIME,
MORE AND MORE SPIRITS
HAVE DRIFTED
INTO THIS WORLD.
HUMANS HAVE BEEN FORCED APART,
SETTLING ON THE LION TURTLES
WHO PROTECT THEM
AND LOSING TOUCH
WITH EACH OTHER.
- MOST PEOPLE THINK THEY LIVE
IN THE ONLY HUMAN CITY
IN THE WORLD.
- MOST HUMANS
THINK ONLY OF THEMSELVES,
NO MATTER
HOW MANY OTHERS ARE AROUND.
- WHEN YOU PASS THROUGH ME,
I FEEL AN INCREDIBLE RUSH
OF POWER.
[grunting]
I FEEL LIKE I'M CHANGING.
THE MORE WE PRACTICE,
THE STRONGER I BECOME.
[sniffs]
SMELLS LIKE SMOKE.
- HUMANS ARE NEARBY.
- LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
- A SPIRIT!
- EASY THERE, FELLAS.
WE'RE FRIENDLY.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
WAN?
- JAYA!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING OUT HERE?
- HA HA!
YOU INSPIRED US.
ONCE WE HEARD THAT YOU SURVIVED
OUT IN THE WILDS,
WE DECIDED TO TRY IT TOO.
- WHERE'S YAO?
DID HE COME WITH YOU?
- YES, BUT SADLY
HE DIDN'T MAKE IT.
WE--WE LOST A LOT
OF GOOD MEN ALONG THE WAY.
SO WHY WERE YOU PROTECTING
THIS SPIRIT?
- THIS IS RAAVA.
DON'T WORRY.
SHE'S NOT LIKE THE DARK SPIRITS
YOU'VE PROBABLY RUN INTO.
- DARK SPIRITS?
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
WE THROW FIRE AT ANY SPIRIT
WE SEE AROUND HERE.
JUST LIKE THEY ATTACK ANY MAN.
- YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE DOING!
YOU'RE ONLY MAKING THINGS WORSE.
- THE SPIRITS ARE COMING BACK!
- LET'S WIPE 'EM OUT THIS TIME.
WE'LL BURN DOWN
THIS WHOLE FOREST IF WE HAVE TO.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
WHEN DID YOU BECOME SO VIOLENT?
- YOU SHOWED ME WE COULD CHANGE
THE WORLD IF WE JUST STOPPED
BEING SO AFRAID.
NOW WE'RE DOING IT.
- THIS ISN'T WHAT I HAD IN MIND.
[all shouting]
- GET OUT
OF THE FOREST, HUMANS.
- WAIT.
WE CAN RESOLVE THIS PEACEFULLY.
- STINKY?
YOU CAME BACK.
- IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
- YOU AND RAAVA ARE JUST IN TIME
TO HELP US
CLEAR THESE TREE-KILLING
FIRE-LOVERS OUT OF HERE
JUST LIKE THE OLD DAYS.
- YOU ARE THE ONE
WHO'S GETTING CLEARED OUT.
- THERE'S NO NEED FOR VIOLENCE.
I KNOW THERE MUST BE A WAY
TO WORK OUT A COMPROMISE.
- YOU HAVE
A GOOD HEART, STINKY.
THESE FIRE TOSSERS
AREN'T LIKE YOU.
- SPIRITS LIKE HIM
KILLED OUR FRIENDS.
I CAN'T LET THEM
GET AWAY WITH THAT.
[thunder rumbles]
- [laughs wickedly]
- WE ARE PROTECTORS
OF THE FOREST.
WE WON'T LET YOU
BURN IT DOWN.
- IT'S VAATU.
HE'S GROWING STRONGER,
USING THEIR ANGER
TO TURN THEM TO HIS SIDE.
- [grunts]
- WIPE THEM OUT!
- STOP, PLEASE!
RAAVA, WE NEED TO COMBINE
OUR ENERGIES.
MAYBE THEN WE'LL HAVE
ENOUGH POWER TO STOP THIS.
ENOUGH!
YOU NEED TO STOP FIGHTING NOW
BEFORE YOU DESTROY EACH OTHER.
- [groans]
STINKY, W-WHAT HAPPENED?
- HE'S CONTROLLING
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS.
- WAN, I HAVE TO LEAVE
YOUR BODY, OR I'LL DESTROY YOU.
- NO.
IT'S WORKING.
IF YOU LEAVE,
THE FIGHTING WILL START AGAIN.
- WAN!
[all shouting]
- [sighs]
WE HAVE TO GO BACK.
- DON'T BOTHER.
YOUR HUMAN FRIENDS
HAVE ALREADY BEEN ANNIHILATED.
- NO!
- ENJOY YOUR FINAL DAYS.
SEE YOU AT THE END
OF THE WORLD.
- RAAVA.
- I'M SORRY, WAN.
- WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
I WAS WRONG ABOUT YOU, WAN.
I HAD NO IDEA
THAT HUMANS WERE CAPABLE
OF SUCH NOBILITY
AND COURAGE.
I'M SORRY THAT WE DO NOT HAVE
MUCH MORE TIME TOGETHER.
- LET'S NOT GIVE UP
BEFORE THE BATTLE'S EVEN BEGUN.
WHO KNOWS WHAT WILL HAPPEN?
AFTER ALL, THIS IS
MY FIRST HARMONIC CONVERGENCE.
- THIS IS THE SOUTHERN PORTAL
TO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
HERE VAATU AND I WILL DO BATTLE
ONCE AGAIN
AT THE PLACE
WHERE THE TWO WORLDS MEET.
[rhythmic drumming]
- ARE YOU READY
FOR OUR FINAL BATTLE, RAAVA?
THANKS TO OUR FRIEND
SEPARATING US,
I THINK THIS TIME
I MAY BE RID OF YOU
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
- BEFORE YOU GET TO HER,
YOU'LL HAVE TO GO THROUGH ME.
- NO HUMAN
CAN STAND AGAINST ME.
- HAVEN'T YOU HEARD
THE LEGENDS?
I'M NOT A REGULAR HUMAN
ANYMORE.
[grunts]
UHH!
- I LIVED 10,000 LIFETIMES
BEFORE THE FIRST OF YOUR KIND
CRAWLED OUT OF THE MUD.
- AAH!
OOF--OH!
- IT WAS I WHO BROKE
THROUGH THE DIVIDE
THAT SEPARATED
THE PLANE OF SPIRITS
FROM THE MATERIAL WORLD!
- [grunting]
- TO HATE ME
IS TO GIVE ME BREATH.
TO FIGHT ME
IS TO GIVE ME STRENGTH.
NOW PREPARE
TO FACE OBLIVION!
- [panting]
RAAVA!
THE ONLY WAY TO WIN
IS TOGETHER.
AH!
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
AAH!
[groaning]
Raava:
I HAVE TO LEAVE YOU.
IF I STAY ANY LONGER,
YOU WILL DIE.
- IT DOESN'T MATTER.
IF YOU LEAVE ME NOW,
VAATU WILL DESTROY EVERYTHING.
WE HAVE TO FINISH THIS
TOGETHER!
- THE HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
IS ABOUT TO BEGIN.
THE ERA OF RAAVA IS OVER.
[boom]
[thunder claps]
[cries out]
- AAH!
Raava:
WE ARE BONDED FOREVER.
- THIS IS YOUR PRISON NOW.
AND I WILL CLOSE THE PORTAL
SO NO HUMAN WILL EVER BE ABLE
TO PHYSICALLY ENTER
THE SPIRIT WORLD
AND RELEASE YOU.
THE SPIRITS MUST STOP
FIGHTING WITH HUMANS
AND RETURN TO THEIR HOME
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD.
I WILL TEACH MEN
TO RESPECT THE SPIRITS
SO THAT BALANCE
WILL BE MAINTAINED.
I WILL BE THE BRIDGE
BETWEEN OUR TWO WORLDS.
[sweeping orchestration]
♪ ♪
THE WORLD IS ENTERING A NEW AGE.
OUR TIME PROTECTING MANKIND
IS OVER.
WE WILL NO LONGER
GIVE HUMANS
THE POWER OF THE ELEMENTS.
[echoing gunshots]
- DIFFERENT GROUPS OF PEOPLE
MUST LEARN TO LIVE TOGETHER.
THIS IS MY MISSION--
TO USE RAAVA'S LIGHT SPIRIT
TO GUIDE THE WORLD
TOWARD PEACE.
- I'M SORRY, RAAVA.
I FAILED TO BRING PEACE.
EVEN WITH VAATU LOCKED AWAY,
DARKNESS STILL SURROUNDS
HUMANITY.
THERE WASN'T ENOUGH TIME.
Raava:
DON'T WORRY.
WE WILL BE TOGETHER
FOR ALL OF YOUR LIFETIMES.
AND WE WILL NEVER GIVE UP.
- [exhales]
[sweeping orchestration]
♪ ♪
[baby crying]
- [gasps]
I REMEMBER.
- DO YOU KNOW WHO YOU ARE?
- MY NAME IS KORRA.
I'M THE AVATAR.
- WE'VE BEEN RAISING
THIS HERD OF AIR BISON
SINCE THE HUNDRED YEAR WAR.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D BE ABLE
TO PRESENT ONE TO THE AVATAR.
- THANK YOU
FOR ALL YOUR KINDNESS.
I WONDER HOW LONG
I'VE BEEN AWAY.
- THAT I CANNOT SAY,
BUT YOU DO NOT HAVE
MUCH TIME LEFT.
THE HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
IS ONLY WEEKS AWAY.
- I HAVE TO CLOSE
THE SPIRIT PORTAL
BEFORE THAT HAPPENS.
♪ ♪
[bison grunts]
[dramatic music]