- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
male narrator:
KORRA HAS REGAINED HER MEMORY!
BY CONNECTING
WITH THE ORIGINAL AVATAR,
KORRA LEARNED
THAT TO STOP UNALAQ
SHE MUST CLOSE THE SPIRIT PORTAL
BEFORE HARMONIC CONVERGENCE,
WHICH IS ONLY WEEKS AWAY!
MEANWHILE, VARRICK
HAS MADE BOLIN INTO A MOVER STAR
AND SAVED ASAMI'S COMPANY.
MAKO IS THE ONLY ONE
WHO SUSPECTS
THAT VARRICK IS UP TO NO GOOD,
BUT CAN HE PROVE IT?
- GOTCHA!
FURRY-FOOT, COME BACK.
[laughs]
- [purring]
- [laughs]
- JINORA, THERE YOU ARE.
COME ON, EVERYONE'S WAITING.
WERE YOU PLAYING WITH SOMEONE?
- OH, JUST SOME
IMAGINARY FRIENDS.
[laughs]
- STOP TELLING LIES.
- IT'S TRUE!
I ONCE BEAT AN EARTHBENDER
IN A ROCK-THROWING CONTEST!
I HAVE THE TROPHY TO PROVE IT.
- ALL RIGHT, WHO'S READY
FOR AN EXCITING TOUR
OF THE EASTERN AIR TEMPLE?
WE'VE GOT A LOT TO SEE TODAY
INCLUDING ANCIENT STATUES,
ANCIENT GARDENS,
AND THE MEDITATION HALL
USED BY ANCIENT AIRBENDERS.
- YAY.
OLD THINGS.
- KORRA?
all: KORRA!
YAY, KORRA.
- KORRA'S BACK.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- AND HOW DID YOU KNOW
WHERE TO FIND US?
- TENZIN'S ITINERARY.
WE WENT OVER IT
LIKE A HUNDRED TIMES
BEFORE WE LEFT REPUBLIC CITY.
- SEE?
THIS IS WHY
SCHEDULES ARE IMPORTANT.
- IT'S SO GREAT
TO SEE YOU ALL AGAIN.
- IT'S GREAT TO SEE YOU TOO,
BUT WHY AREN'T YOU TRAINING
AT THE SOUTH POLE?
- WAIT, YOU DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THE CIVIL WAR?
- WHAT?
NO.
WE'VE BEEN OUT OF TOUCH
WITH THE OUTSIDE WORLD
SINCE WE STARTED OUR VACATION.
- TENZIN'S IDEA.
WHAT HAPPENED?
- SO MUCH.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE TO START.
- JUST TELL US EVERYTHING!
- EVERYTHING?
OKAY.
I OPENED A SPIRIT PORTAL
AT THE SOUTH POLE,
BUT THEN UNALAQ
TURNED OUT TO BE A BAD GUY
AND WANTED TO TAKE CONTROL
OF THE SOUTH,
SO I SORT OF STARTED
A CIVIL WAR,
BUT WHEN I WENT TO
FIND SOME HELP,
I WAS ATTACKED BY MY COUSINS
AND THEN BY
A GIANT, DARK SPIRIT,
AND THEN I FORGOT WHO I WAS,
AND THEN I MET THE FIRST AVATAR,
AND THEN I REALIZED
I SHOULDN'T HAVE OPENED
THE PORTAL IN THE FIRST PLACE,
AND NOW I NEED TO
CLOSE IT AGAIN!
- I KNEW THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
SO AVATAR WAN IMPRISONED
THIS DARK SPIRIT VAATU
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD?
- YES, AND NOW I THINK MY UNCLE
IS TRYING TO FREE HIM.
- I KNEW UNALAQ
WAS HUNGRY FOR POWER
BUT NEVER REALIZED
HOW FAR HE WOULD GO TO GET IT.
- THIS IS ALL MY FAULT.
- NO, DON'T BLAME YOURSELF.
THIS IS UNALAQ'S DOING.
NOW, WE MUST FOCUS
ON SETTING THINGS RIGHT
BEFORE HE CAN DO
ANY MORE DAMAGE.
- THANK YOU.
- SO YOU NEED TO CLOSE
THE SOUTHERN PORTAL,
BUT IF UNALAQ'S ARMY
CONTROLS THE SOUTH,
HOW ARE WE GOING TO GET TO IT?
- I THOUGHT ABOUT THAT.
MY BEST CHANCE TO CLOSE
THE PORTAL IS FROM THE INSIDE.
I HAVE TO ENTER
THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- A JOURNEY TO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
ALL MY YEARS
OF SPIRITUAL TRAINING
HAVE PREPARED ME
FOR THIS MOMENT.
I WILL HELP YOU.
TODAY, WE ENTER
THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- FATHER,
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
- YOU'RE HERE TO STRAIGHTEN OUT
THE MESS YOU CAUSED
WHEN YOU FAILED
TO CAPTURE THE AVATAR.
- I TOLD YOU,
IT WASN'T OUR FAULT.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT WAS MY FAULT
FOR TRUSTING YOU.
HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
IS ALMOST UPON US.
THIS IS MY OPPORTUNITY
TO CHANGE THE WORLD.
- WE'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU,
FATHER.
- GOOD,
BECAUSE I'LL NEED YOUR HELP
TO OPEN THE NORTHERN PORTAL.
- I THOUGHT ONLY
THE AVATAR COULD DO IT.
- I BELIEVE
THERE IS ANOTHER WAY.
THIS WAY.
THERE IT IS:
THE NORTHERN PORTAL.
- [screams]
- CUT!
OKAY, THAT'S LUNCH, EVERYONE.
[bell rings]
- HELLO?
ANYONE?
NUKTUK'S STILL UP HERE,
ALL ALONE.
[door slams]
[footsteps]
ASAMI!
HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- VARRICK INVITED ME
TO WATCH SOME OF THE FILMING.
ARE YOU FILMING RIGHT NOW?
- RIGHT NOW?
NOPE.
WE'RE, UH...
WE'RE AT LUNCH.
- ASAMI, THERE YOU ARE.
IS BOLIN AROUND?
- UP HERE.
- GOOD.
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
TO TELL YOU BOTH.
[screams]
[grunts]
OW.
I GOT TO STOP DOING
MY OWN STUNTS.
- I FOUND OUT WHO'S BEEN
STEALING FROM FUTURE INDUSTRIES:
VARRICK.
- WHAT?
NO.
- HE ATTACKED HIS OWN SHIP?
- YES!
IT WAS A PLOY.
HE WANTS REPUBLIC CITY
TO GO TO WAR,
AND HE WANTS CONTROL
OF THE BUSINESSES
THAT STAND TO PROFIT
THE MOST FROM IT.
HE ALREADY HAD ALL THE SHIPPING.
ALL HE NEEDED
WAS FUTURE INDUSTRIES.
- VARRICK HELPED SAVE
FUTURE INDUSTRIES.
HE'S MY BUSINESS PARTNER NOW,
NOT AN EVIL MASTERMIND.
MAKO, YOU SEEM STRESSED.
- I AM STRESSED!
- SEE, THIS IS WHY
I HAD TO MOVE OUT.
- YOU GUYS AREN'T
LIVING TOGETHER ANYMORE?
- NOPE.
IT WAS TIME FOR THIS EAGLE-HAWK
TO SPREAD HIS WINGS
AND FLY.
- SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE HAD
A PRETTY BUSY WEEK.
MAYBE YOU JUST NEED TO RELAX.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
ARE YOU TWO--
YOU'RE DATING AGAIN!
WHAT?
- DATING?
NO!
- THAT'S CRAZY!
- KORRA JUST LEFT A WEEK AGO!
- GUYS, LISTEN TO ME.
VARRICK IS UP TO NO GOOD,
AND I HAVE PROOF.
THE DETONATORS
HE USES IN HIS MOVERS
ARE EXACTLY LIKE
THE ONE I FOUND
AT THE CULTURAL
CENTER ATTACK.
AND THOSE EXPLOSIONS
WERE EXACTLY LIKE THE ONES
THE CAPTAIN REPORTED WHEN
ASAMI'S SHIPMENT WAS HIJACKED.
DON'T YOU SEE?
- ANYONE COULD HAVE
GOTTEN THEIR HANDS
ON ONE OF THOSE
DETONATORS.
- YEAH.
LET IT GO, MAKO.
LET IT GO.
- NO!
I'M NOT GOING TO LET IT GO!
- VARRICK'S BEEN LOOKING
FOR YOU.
- YOU'RE LUCKY.
THIS TEMPLE
IS THE MOST SPIRITUAL
OF ALL THE AIR TEMPLES.
WHY, THIS VERY GARDEN IS WHERE
MY FATHER MET GURU PATHIK.
- WOW!
SPIRIT WORLD, HERE WE COME.
[bell clanging]
[low droning sound]
- ARE YOU IN THE SPIRIT WORLD?
- I WOULD BE
IF MEELO COULD RING HIS BELL
AT THE APPROPRIATE INTERVALS.
- AWW, DID I DO IT WRONG?
- LET'S TRY SOMETHING ELSE.
- I THOUGHT YOUR BELL RINGING
WAS JUST FINE.
- THANKS!
[bell clanging]
[ethereal music]
♪ ♪
- [coughs]
KYA, THIS IS TOO MUCH SMOKE.
YOU SET IT UP WRONG.
THIS ISN'T GOING TO WORK.
- I'M SORRY.
I DID WHAT YOU TOLD ME.
- WELL, THE MOMENT'S RUINED.
- WE COULD HAVE TRIED
A LITTLE LONGER.
- [squealing]
- COME BACK, FURRY-FOOT!
- HEY, JINORA,
WHAT ARE YOU CHASING?
- NOTHING.
- FOCUS, KORRA.
FOCUS.
- I AM FOCUSING.
- NO TALKING.
FEEL THE ENERGY OF THE UNIVERSE.
- OKAY, I FEEL IT.
- KORRA, REALLY!
I'M TRYING TO CONCENTRATE HERE!
I DON'T THINK THIS LOCATION
IS GOING TO WORK EITHER.
- WHAT'S GOING ON WITH YOU?
FIRST, YOU'RE BLAMING MEELO,
THEN KYA, AND NOW ME.
- WELL, NOTHING IS
FEELING RIGHT TO ME.
- I DON'T WANT TO
RUSH YOUR FEELINGS,
BUT WE'RE KIND OF
IN A HURRY.
HOW DID YOU FIRST GET INTO
THE SPIRIT WORLD?
LET'S TRY THAT.
- WELL...
ACTUALLY, I'VE NEVER BEEN
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD?
- BUT YOU USED TO SPEND DAYS
IN THE TEMPLE MEDITATING.
- TRYING TO GET IN.
IT NEVER HAPPENED.
IT'S MY GREATEST SHORTCOMING
AS AN AIRBENDER,
SPIRITUAL LEADER,
AND SON OF AANG.
- [laughs]
WELCOME TO
THE "I DISAPPOINT DAD" CLUB.
- IF YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
TO THE SPIRIT WORLD,
HOW WERE YOU PLANNING
TO GET KORRA INTO IT?
- I'VE SPENT YEARS STUDYING
THE TECHNIQUES AND THEORIES
OF ANCIENT SPIRITUAL LEADERS.
NOW THAT THE AVATAR NEEDS ME,
IT MUST BE MY TIME.
- TENZIN, HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
IS ALMOST HERE.
IF VAATU ESCAPES
FROM THE SPIRIT WORLD--
- YOU HAVE TO TRUST ME.
I CAN HELP YOU.
- THERE MIGHT BE ANOTHER WAY.
JINORA, IS THERE SOMETHING
YOU WANT TO TELL KORRA?
- JINORA?
SHE IS TOO YOUNG
AND UNTRAINED
TO HAVE ANY KNOWLEDGE
ABOUT SPIRITUAL MATTERS.
- ACTUALLY, I THINK I DO KNOW
WHERE KORRA NEEDS TO GO
TO GET INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- AND HOW WOULD YOU KNOW THAT?
- MY SPIRIT FRIENDS SHOWED ME.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU CAN SHOW YOURSELVES.
[all gasp]
- HOW DID YOU DO THAT?
- JINORA.
- BUNNIES!
- ACTUALLY, THEY'RE
DRAGONFLY-BUNNY SPIRITS.
- I KNEW IT.
LOOKS LIKE
SHE DOES KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT SPIRITUAL MATTERS.
[both laughing]
- SO CUTE.
- BUNNIES!
COME BACK!
- HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE
TO DO THIS?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I'VE ALWAYS KIND OF
HAD A CONNECTION WITH SPIRITS.
- [laughing]
I THINK THIS ONE LIKES ME.
- ARE THEY HERE TO HELP?
- I THINK THEY WANT YOU
TO GO DOWN THERE.
- I DON'T KNOW.
THE SPIRITUAL ENERGY
IS HISTORICALLY STRONGEST
NEAR THE TEMPLE.
- NO OFFENSE,
BUT I'M GUESSING THE SPIRITS
HAVE ACTUALLY BEEN
TO THE SPIRIT WORLD,
SO I'M GONNA FOLLOW THEM.
- IF WE NEED TO GO
TO THE TENZIN WORLD,
WE'LL CALL YOU.
- FATHER, HAVEN'T THE SPIRITS
HAD 10,000 YEARS
TO OPEN THIS PORTAL?
- IF THEY COULD NOT SUCCEED,
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK WE WILL?
- BY ENTERING THE SPIRIT WORLD
THROUGH THE PORTAL,
WE BRING WITH US
SOMETHING THE SPIRITS NEVER HAD:
OUR BENDING.
JOIN ME!
TOGETHER WE CAN
OPEN THIS PORTAL.
- [grunts]
[groaning]
- DESNA!
- LEAVE HIM.
KEEP BENDING!
- HE NEEDS A HEALER AT ONCE!
- THIS IS MORE IMPORTANT!
- I'M TAKING HIM BACK.
[grunting]
[steady hum]
[ice shattering]
- I HEAR YOU'VE GOT SOME IDEAS.
YOU WANNA TELL ME ABOUT THEM?
- GO AHEAD.
TORTURE ME ALL YOU WANT.
I'M NOT GONNA TALK.
- TORTURE?
THE ONLY THING I WANT TO TORTURE
IS THIS PESKY FOOT FUNGUS.
OOH!
AH!
EEE!
OOH!
[sighs]
THE BURNING MEANS
IT'S WORKING.
I HEARD YOU'VE BEEN
INVESTIGATING
THE RECENT ATTACKS ON MY SHIPS,
AND I THINK YOU KNOW THAT I KNOW
THAT YOU KNOW, YOU KNOW?
- KNOW WHAT?
- THAT THE WORLD
IS A DANGEROUS PLACE,
AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHY
I WANT TO OFFER YOU
A JOB ON MY SECURITY FORCE.
- I HAVE A JOB.
- WE NEED YOU.
ME, ASAMI, BOLIN.
WE'RE ALL ON THE SAME TEAM HERE.
WE WANT YOU TO JOIN US.
- YOU WOULDN'T WANT ANYTHING
TO HAPPEN TO ASAMI, WOULD YOU?
I MEAN, I HEARD YOU AND HER
WERE KIND OF AN ITEM AGAIN.
OR WHAT ABOUT YOUR BROTHER?
- WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
- I'M SAYING I WANT YOUR HELP
TO PROTECT THEM.
WITHOUT YOU,
WHO KNOWS WHAT COULD HAPPEN.
- THANKS FOR YOUR CONCERN,
BUT THE ANSWER IS NO.
[Oogi grumbling]
- [squealing]
- OH, YOU ARE JUST SO CUTE.
I'M GOING TO NAME YOU BUM-JU.
IT'S SHORT FOR "BUMI, JUNIOR."
DON'T YOU THINK
HE LOOKS LIKE ME?
- THE RESEMBLANCE IS UNCANNY.
- I THINK DAD'S MAD AT ME.
- YOUR FATHER'S NOT MAD.
HIS PRIDE'S
JUST A LITTLE BRUISED
SINCE HE ISN'T ABLE
TO SEE SPIRITS LIKE YOU.
- YOU HAVE A NATURAL GIFT.
THAT'S PRETTY LUCKY.
- YOU'RE THE LUCKY ONE.
YOU ACTUALLY GOT TO MEET
THE FIRST AVATAR.
I KNOW ABOUT A LOT OF AVATARS,
BUT I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT HIM.
IS IT EVEN A HIM,
OR IS IT A HER?
- IT'S A HIM,
AVATAR WAN.
HE WAS AMAZING.
I SAW HOW HE BECAME
THE FIRST AVATAR
BY FUSING WITH RAAVA,
THE SPIRIT OF LIGHT.
- THE AVATAR IS PART SPIRIT?
OF COURSE!
JUST LIKE THE STATUE!
- WHAT STATUE?
- WHEN WE WERE
AT THE SOUTHERN AIR TEMPLE,
I WAS DRAWN TO THIS OLD CARVING.
I COULDN'T FIGURE OUT
WHAT IT WAS UNTIL NOW.
IT WAS THE FIRST AVATAR.
- WHEN DID THIS HAPPEN?
- IT WAS ON THE SOLSTICE.
- THAT'S THE DAY
I OPENED THE SOUTHERN PORTAL.
both: WHOA.
[Oogi groans]
- WE'RE HERE!
- ARE YOU SURE THESE SPIRITS
ARE LEADING US
TO THE RIGHT PLACE?
- OF COURSE!
I TRUST BUM-JU WITH MY LIFE.
- LOOK.
- THERE ARE CARVINGS ON THEM.
- THIS IS AN ANCIENT AIRBENDER
MEDITATION CIRCLE.
- THERE'S A LOT OF
SPIRITUAL ENERGY IN THIS PLACE,
BUT IT FEELS REALLY STRANGE.
- WE'LL HAVE TO PERFORM
A SPIRITUAL CLEANSING CEREMONY.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- DAD TAUGHT IT TO ME.
THIS SITE HAS BEEN NEGLECTED
FOR MANY YEARS.
A CLEANSING CEREMONY WILL HELP
STRENGTHEN ITS CONNECTION
TO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- GOOD JOB,
YOU CLEANSED THE AREA
OF THE ONLY SPIRITS
THAT WANT TO HELP US,
AND YOU SCARED AWAY BUM-JU.
- IT'S WORKING.
[low rumbling]
boom!
[screaming]
[bats shrieking]
- AH!
BATS!
EVIL BATS!
- NOT BATS.
DARK SPIRITS!
- WHAT ARE WE SUPPOSED TO DO?
- AMAZING.
- YOUR SPIRITUAL TRAINING
HAS COME A LONG WAY.
- UNALAQ MAY BE
A HORRIBLE PERSON,
BUT HIS SPIRIT POWERS
ARE NO JOKE.
- HE TAUGHT YOU HOW TO
TRANSFORM DARK SPIRITS.
I CAN'T EVEN GET YOU
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- EVERYTHING UNALAQ TAUGHT ME
WAS TO HELP HIMSELF.
EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE
WAS MEANT TO HELP ME.
I AM SO SORRY FOR TURNING
MY BACK ON YOU AS MY MENTOR.
I NEED YOU NOW MORE THAN EVER.
- I WON'T LET YOU DOWN.
THE ANCIENT AIRBENDERS
MUST HAVE BUILT THIS SITE.
IF WE MEDITATE HERE,
WE'LL BE ABLE
TO ENTER THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- WHY DON'T YOU GO FIRST?
- AFTER ALL THESE YEARS,
MY FATHER'S DREAM FOR ME
WILL FINALLY COME TRUE.
[knocks on door]
- HI.
- DID YOU COME BY TO TELL ME
HOW PARANOID I AM?
- NO.
I JUST WANTED TO COME BY
TO MAKE SURE YOU'RE OKAY.
YOU SEEMED SO AGITATED EARLIER.
- I'M FINE.
- MAYBE YOU NEED A NIGHT OFF.
WHY DON'T WE GO GET SOME DINNER?
- NO, THANKS.
I'M A LITTLE BUSY.
- TOO BUSY FOR KWONG'S CUISINE?
REMEMBER?
WE HAD OUR FIRST DATE THERE.
- MAYBE I DO NEED TO
GET MY MIND OFF THINGS.
[knocks on door]
- POLICE!
HEY, MAKO.
HOPE WE DIDN'T INTERRUPT
YOU TWO LOVEBIRDS.
- WHAT'S GOING ON?
- WE BUSTED SOME TRIPLE THREATS
WHO SAID YOU HIRED THEM
FOR A JOB.
- ALL RIGHT.
IT'S TRUE.
WE WERE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHO STOLE ASAMI'S STUFF,
SO WE HIRED THEM
FOR A STING OPERATION.
I'M SORRY FOR
GOING BEHIND YOUR BACK.
- ACCORDING TO
THE TRIPLE THREATS,
YOU DID MORE THAN THAT.
THEY SAID YOU HELPED THEM STEAL
A WAREHOUSE FULL OF
FUTURE INDUSTRIES PROPERTY.
- THAT'S CRAZY!
- YOU'RE GONNA BELIEVE
A BUNCH OF CRIMINALS?
- I HAVE TO FOLLOW UP ON A LEAD.
- WELL, LOOKY WHAT I FOUND:
CASH...
AND THESE.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH EXPLOSIVES, MAKO?
- I DON'T KNOW
WHERE THOSE CAME FROM.
- YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
- NONE OF THAT IS MINE.
- SHOULD'VE KNOWN YOU'D HOOK UP
WITH YOUR OLD PALS.
ONCE A TRIPLE THREAT,
ALWAYS A TRIPLE THREAT.
- THIS HAS TO BE A MISTAKE.
- SORRY TO BREAK THE NEWS
TO YOU, SWEETIE,
BUT YOUR BOYFRIEND'S
JUST A CROOKED COP.
THAT STING OPERATION
WAS JUST A WAY
TO LURE YOU AWAY
FROM YOUR WAREHOUSE.
[laughs]
HE WAS USING YOU
THE WHOLE TIME.
- THAT'S NOT TRUE, ASAMI.
I WOULD NEVER DO ANYTHING
TO HURT YOU.
IT'S VARRICK.
THIS IS ALL VARRICK.
HE SET ME UP!
- YEAH, IT'S VARRICK'S FAULT.
VARRICK.
[laughs]
- YOU IN THE SPIRIT WORLD YET?
- NO, I AM NOT,
AND STOP BUGGING ME.
[wood clattering]
- IT'S OKAY, TENZIN.
MAYBE YOU WEREN'T MEANT TO
GUIDE KORRA
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- NO!
JUST GIVE ME SOME TIME.
- STOP BEING SO STUBBORN.
IT'S NOT YOUR DESTINY.
I THINK JINORA WAS MEANT TO
GUIDE THE AVATAR.
- JINORA WILL NOT ENTER
THE SPIRIT WORLD!
SHE'S NOT READY FOR THE DANGERS
OF THE OTHER SIDE,
BUT I AM.
I'VE SPENT YEARS TRAINING,
STUDYING,
AND MASTERING
EVERYTHING THERE IS TO KNOW
ABOUT THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- TENZIN, WE'RE RUNNING
OUT OF TIME.
- IF EVERYONE
COULD JUST BE QUIET
AND LET ME FOCUS.
- AUNT KYA IS RIGHT.
I CAN GUIDE KORRA
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
- PERHAPS I WILL NEVER HAVE
THE CONNECTION WITH SPIRITS
LIKE I ALWAYS WANTED...
LIKE MY FATHER
WANTED ME TO HAVE.
- IT'S OKAY, DADDY.
- I'M PROUD OF YOU.
GO.
CLOSE THE PORTAL.
WE'LL WAIT HERE
AND KEEP YOUR BODIES SAFE
TILL YOU RETURN.
- WE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
THE SPIRIT WORLD.
- THE AVATAR IS DEAD,
AND WE CANNOT OPEN
THE NORTHERN PORTAL.
I HAVE FAILED YOU, VAATU.
- YOU HAVE NOT FAILED ME...
YET.
THE AVATAR STILL LIVES.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW?
- EVEN THOUGH MY CONNECTION
TO RAAVA WAS SEVERED,
I CAN STILL FEEL HER PRESENCE.
- I'LL FIND HER.
- THE AVATAR WILL FIND YOU.
SHE HAS JUST ENTERED
THE SPIRIT WORLD.