Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
Unalaq has forced Korra
into opening the northern portal
and trapped Jinora in the spirit world.
Back in Republic City,
everybody loves
Varrick's Nuktuk movers.
Everybody, that is, except Mako,
whose pursuit of Varrick
has landed him in the slammer.
And in the Southern Water Tribe,
Unalaq's army is nearing victory
in the civil war,
but Tonraq isn't about
to give up without a fight.
- Dad's back!
- Where's Jinora?
No!
- Her spirit is trapped
in the spirit world,
but she's going to be all right.
- How could this happen?
- It was all my fault.
I should have never let Jinora
enter the spirit world without me.
I couldn't protect her.
- I'm so sorry, Pema.
I tried to save her,
but Unalaq tricked me.
- Don't worry, honey,
I'm not going to stop
until our little girl
is back safe with us.
- You've got a visitor.
- Hey, Mako.
- Hey.
What's with the fancy duds?
- I'm on my way to the big finale
for "Nuktuk: Hero of the South."
Yeah, everyone's gonna be there,
except for, you know, you...
because you're in jail and stuff.
- Thanks for the reminder.
- Hey, I brought you something.
I thought this would
brighten up your new place.
Read the inscription.
- "Dear Mako,
Nuktuk says, 'Keep smiling.'"
Did you come by
just to give me a poster?
- No, I came by to give you my sincere,
heartfelt words of encouragement.
I know our lives have been moving
in two different directions,
but I want you to know
that I will always be there for you.
We are brothers, after all,
even if one of us is
a member of high society
and the other one is a criminal.
- I am not a criminal!
- Of course I know that,
but you do kinda look like one,
'cause you're in a jail,
and that's where criminals live.
- I was set up!
Varrick knew I had figured out
he was hiring gangsters
to pose as Northern soldiers
to get Republic City
to join the war.
That's why he had me arrested.
- Ah, I see what you're doing.
You're going for the insanity defense.
Smart.
- No!
I'm trying to tell you that
Varrick isn't what he seems.
Where's Asami?
She'll listen to me.
- I asked her to come,
but she said it was too hard for her.
You being in jail like this
reminds her of her dad.
Okay, gotta run,
but I'll be back tomorrow.
And I am gonna get you
the best attorney
fame and fortune can buy.
- Bolin, wait.
If my theory about Varrick is right,
something might go down tonight
at your premiere.
Promise me
you'll keep your eyes peeled.
Yeah, okay, big brother.
I promise.
Whew! That insanity defense
is definitely gonna work.
- Should we wait another day?
Korra still might come
with reinforcements.
- We can't wait any longer.
It's time we take back what is ours!
It's time to take back our city!
- Say "Nuktuk."
- There they are, folks,
the sweethearts of the big screen,
and Republic City's most famous couple,
Bolin and Ginger.
- Let me get a picture.
- Wow, that was fun.
And did you hear what Shiro said?
We're Republic City's
most famous couple.
- Bolin, you're a doll,
but you're as dumb
as the rocks you bend.
We are not a couple.
- That's not what Shiro said.
- Stop stuffing your mustaches
with Varri-cakes
and get to your post!
- You got it, Boss.
- You two are the pinnacle
of refinement.
- This star-studded event
just keeps getting
star-studdier, folks.
President Raiko
and the First Lady,
Buttercup Raiko,
just arrived.
And they're being greeted
by entrepreneur extraordinaire,
Varrick.
- There they are,
my two most honored guests.
Mwah!
What do you think?
No expense has been spared.
I brought in the finest
entertainers from Ba Sing Se
and the best food
from around the world.
Heck, I even had this red carpet
imported from the Fire Nation.
They make the best red stuff
over there.
Fact!
All right, picture time!
- Varrick, you didn't
have to do all this for us.
- I wanted to.
Mr. President,
I took one look at your wife,
and I knew that you
were a man of exquisite taste.
And that's why I know
you're gonna love this mover!
- Varrick,
I know what you're doing,
and I doubt your propaganda
is going to change my mind
about going to war
with the Northern Water Tribe.
- Oh, I think you'll be surprised
how persuasive I can be.
Thank you all for coming to the finale
of "Nuktuk: Hero of the South."
You know,
when I first started this project,
there were a lot
of naysayers out there.
"You can't make pictures move,"
they said.
"You can't take
some knucklehead Earthbender
and make him a star,"
they said.
"You can't teach
a polar bear dog to speak," they said.
Well, they're wrong.
Thanks to the magic
of the movers,
our furry friends
have found their voices.
And you'll be shocked to hear
what they have to say.
They speak of the injustice
that's happening
in the Southern Water Tribe right now.
My hope is that their words
and this epic mover
will inspire a real-life hero
to rise up and help.
Thank you again.
Enjoy the show.
- When last we left our hero,
he was captured by the evil Unalaq's
dastardly pet bird.
Amazingly, with the power
of his whistling,
Nuktuk escaped...
- And decided to seek out counsel.
- Thank you, wise sage.
I will travel to Republic City
and seek help.
- Have a seat.
I'm just working on a cure
for the common cold.
No longer will my citizens
suffer from the sniffles.
- Mr. President,
there's something more important
than the sniffles right now.
I need your help
to stop the evil Unalaq.
- Did you say "help"?
If there is one thing I love doing,
it's helping people-
- The seal-lion
seemed a bit far-fetched,
but the portrayal of this president
is right on the money.
- I think this is your best mover yet.
- I just wish Mako was here to see it.
- Mmm. I like to eat the top
off the Varri-cake first.
- I just try to shove the whole thing
in my mouth at once.
I love our job.
- Huh?
- Northern Water Tribe automatons!
Nooo!
- Bee bo bop,
Nuktuk cannot stop Unalaq.
Must destroy Nuktuk.
- Ha ha!
Aah!
- Looks like you forgot
that water and automatons
don't mix.
- Beep bop boo.
Oh, no, circuits not working.
We did it!
But wait.
Where's Juji?
- Nuk-no!
- You can't die, Juji.
Not on my watch.
It's okay, Nuktuk.
At least I got to be...
Your friend.
" Juji!
- Are you okay?
It seems like this mover
is really getting to you.
You do know Juji's not really dead?
- Of course I know.
Juji's fine.
He comes back to life in the end
when the doomsday device shifts
the polarity of the Earth.
Oops. Spoiler.
Sorry.
- Then what's wrong?
- I guess I just miss my friends.
Everything is going so well for me,
but it feels empty
without everyone around.
Korra's gone, Mako's in jail,
you're doing...
business lady stuff.
Team Avatar's fallen apart.
- I know.
Things have changed so much
since we first met.
Why don't you come back in
and finish watching
the mover with me?
- You go ahead.
I need another minute.
That's weird.
Whoa--ahh!
Ugh!
- They're after the president!
- You're too late, Nuktuk.
Soon, my doomsday device
will shoot this block of ice
into the earth's core,
freezing the entire planet.
And I will be the ruler of Ice Earth!
- I don't think so.
I don't think so!
- Huh! Ha!
- Mr. President, get back!
I'm here to help.
Looks like there's nowhere to go.
- Secure the president
and call for backup immediately!
- Nuktuk, look out!
- Bolin, look out!
- Hyah!
- This is unbelievable!
Bolin is bending two full stacks
of earth discs at once,
which would normally be illegal.
But then again, he's fighting
three Waterbenders,
so all rules are out the window.
- Tell me who sent you!
- It was Varrick.
Please don't hurt me, Nuktuk!
- I think this is our cue to exit.
- Where do you think you're going?
- It's a knockout!
- They're falling back.
- Varrick's plan was to kidnap you
and blame it on the North.
Then Republic City would have no choice
but to join the war
on the side of the South.
- I can't believe Varrick
would do something like this,
and no one saw it coming.
- Actually, someone did.
Remember Mako?
- You've got a great officer
on your hands.
- He's one of the best.
- Mwah!
I can't believe my boyfriend
is a real-life hero.
- Boyfriend?
Wait, stop.
I thought you said
we weren't a couple.
- You really are as dumb
as those rocks.
Of course we're a couple.
- Bolin, you saved the president.
And you proved Mako was right all along.
We have to go tell him what happened.
- Yeah.
- Oh, you meant right now.
- President Raiko...
- Avatar Korra, what's wrong?
- Sir, I know I've asked
for your help before,
but things have changed.
Unalaq doesn't just want
to take over the South anymore.
He wants to destroy the whole world.
- Unalaq is gonna destroy the world?
He really does have a doomsday device?
- He's trying to release
a powerful dark spirit
during harmonic convergence,
which is only a few days away.
If he succeeds,
the world as we know it is over.
Sir, we desperately need your help.
- I'm sorry, Korra,
but my answer is still no.
- There are lives on the line!
And my daughter is one of them.
Raiko, you must reconsider.
- I'm aware that lives are on the line,
and that's precisely why
my troops are staying here.
If the world is going
to be thrown into chaos,
like you claim,
I need to protect my citizens.
I'm sorry.
- Sir...
Nuktuk needs your help.
I know you love helping people.
- Son, I appreciate you saving my life,
and I'm a big fan of your work,
but my decision is final.
- I never should have saved that guy.
- If you guys need help,
I'm here for you.
- Yeah, me too.
- Thank you.
It's so good to see you guys again.
Wait, where's Mako?
- So how was the big premiere?
- I saved the president!
In real life!
- Wait, what?
- You were right about Varrick.
He tried to kidnap Raiko!
- I knew it.
- But it didn't work, because of you.
And because of me.
Let's just say we both did good.
Beifong says you're free to go.
Sorry for ever doubting you, Mako.
- Don't worry about it, bro.
- Nice job, Mako.
You're going to make a great detective.
- But, Chief, there aren't any
detective openings right now.
- Actually, we have two openings.
- Mwah.
Mako, I missed you so much.
- Oh, yeah, did I forget to tell you?
Korra's back.
- Korra, hey,
I missed you too.
So you're not still mad at me?
- Why would I be mad?
- We had that fight
before you left, remember?
- No, not really.
I got attacked by a dark spirit,
and I lost my memory for a little while.
Maybe it hasn't all come back yet.
Was it a bad fight?
- Uh...
mm...no.
No, it-- it wasn't that bad.
- Korra, we don't have much time.
We need to figure out
how to deal with Unalaq.
- I think I know
just the man to talk to.
- Guys, hey!
What do you think?
Varrick Industries built this prison,
and I had this cell made special.
I had a feeling I'd end up here one day.
Zhu Li, come on!
We got guests.
Whip up a pot
of that green tea I love.
- Yes, sir.
- Zhu Li's in prison with you?
- Of course.
I don't go anywhere
without my assistant.
Do you?
- We're not interested in your tea,
and this isn't a friendly visit.
- Don't tell me you guys are still mad
about everything that happened.
I did some good things too.
Korra, who warned you
about Unalaq?
I did.
Bolin, who got you into the movers?
Asami, who saved your company?
I did.
Mako, who got you thrown in jail?
I did!
Oh, yeah,
I guess that was a bad thing.
- You stole everything from me,
and you tried to kidnap the president.
Those are pretty bad too.
- I wasn't going to hurt him.
I just needed to start a war.
Well, a bigger war.
- Well, we're gonna end it.
Where's all the stuff
you stole from Asami?
- The Future Industries stuff?
It's on my battleship.
- You have a battleship?
- Of course I do!
I bought the first one they made,
named her the Zhu Li.
- You named your battleship
after your assistant?
- Yep. They're both cold,
heartless war machines.
- Your tea, sir.
- Look, I am truly sorry
for the mess I caused.
Let me make it up to you.
Take Zhu Li.
My battleship,
it's yours, and everything on it.
- It's not the fleet
we were looking for,
but it's the next best thing.
- All right!
Team Avatar is back in business!
- It's okay.
We're going to stop Unalaq
and get Jinora back.
- I hope my dad's all right.
- I'm sure he's fine.
Get the men and fall back.
- What about you?
- I'm going to end this right now.
Go!
- Hello, Tonraq.
Looking for me?
- Brother,
I'm too strong for you.
- You're no brother of mine.
You betrayed me.
You had me banished.
- Yes, I did.
- Stop!
He's mine.
- You are not the true chief.
- I am.
And you will bow to me.
- Now that I've defeated you,
your daughter is next.