Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
- Bolin's a hero.
The mover star stopped
Varrick's kidnapping attempt
on President Raiko,
proving his brother's innocence.
Mako and Korra were reunited,
but Korra has no memory
of their breakup.
Meanwhile, Jinora's spirit is
still trapped in the spirit world,
and Tonraq and his Southern forces
have been defeated.
Now it's up to team Avatar
to stop Unalaq
before harmonic convergence.
- What's up with the coat?
And where did you get that pie?
- It's a Varrick ship.
You never know what you're gonna find.
There's a whole level
filled with funhouse mirrors.
Of course,
there's also the cat-gator deck.
I miss that guy.
He really knew how to make
a long trip interesting.
So have you told Korra yet
about how
you guys broke up
and then you
kind of started dating Asami
while she was off
getting attacked by dark spirits?
- You wanna keep it down?
I'm waiting for the right moment.
- Oh, Mako.
You know, a wise man once
told me that delivering bad news
to a girlfriend was like
ripping off a blood-sucking leech.
You just have to do it fast
and get it over with.
I hate it when you listen to me.
Fine.
- Unalaq will be waiting for you.
You'll need all of
your Avatar power to stop him.
- I'm going to close the spirit portals,
lock Vaatu in for another 10,000 years,
and make Unalaq wish
he'd never been born!
Thanks, Mako.
- Uh... um...
- Did you want something?
- Uh, no, no, nothing.
- As soon as we reach
the Southern Water Tribe,
we'll blast through the blockade
at the main port.
Then we can rendezvous
with Tonraq and his troops,
crash through the defenses
around the portal,
and enter the spirit world.
- Whoa, since when
does my little brother
want to crash or blast
through anything?
- I'll do whatever it takes
to save my daughter.
- We all want to save Jinora,
but I think your plan
might be a tad overaggressive,
seeing as there are
only seven of us and one ship.
- Really?
And what do you suggest?
- An attack like this
calls for strategy.
I remember
when I was surrounded by pirates
in the Hurricane Straits.
We managed to capture them all
with just a feather, two eggs,
and a barrel of molasses.
- I don't want to hear
any of your crazy stories now.
This is serious.
- Are we almost there?
- Asami: Almost.
But I just picked up a distress signal
from the Southern troops.
There's a problem.
. Mom!
- I'm so happy you're here.
- Where's Dad?
- Unalaq wiped out
the entire Southern resistance
and captured your father.
- I'll get him back.
- Where is my mother?
- She's in the healing hut.
So many injured.
- What happened?
- Her soul is trapped
in the spirit world.
- Oh, my goodness.
How long has she been away?
- Almost a week.
I've tried to keep her energy flowing,
but I can feel her slipping away.
You're the only one
who can help her now, Mom.
- How much longer
can she survive like this?
- I don't know.
But she's very strong
to have lasted this long.
- I talked to the rebels.
They said Unalaq's got
the southern portal surrounded.
Harmonic convergence
is only a few hours away.
- Then we have to break through
the enemy lines ourselves
and get to the portal now.
- There's no use in talking anymore.
We know what our mission is.
- A suicide mission.
- You know, I was
in a similar situation once.
My platoon had crawled
through the desert
with no water for a week,
but when we finally located
the only oasis for 100 miles,
it was surrounded
by angry Sandbenders.
I realized our only chance
to get to the water
was to drop in from above.
So I fashioned together a catapult,
and with the help of
a few well-trained hog-monkeys--
- Enough of your ridiculous lies.
Can't you see
that the fate of the world
and Jinora's life depends
on what we do here today?
- Hold on.
Maybe Bumi's right.
We don't have a catapult
and hog-monkeys,
but we have a flying bison,
and there's a plane on Varrick's ship.
Maybe we can attack from above.
- What are you thinking?
- Mako, Bolin,
and I can use the plane
to create a distraction
and scatter some of the defenses.
You, Tenzin, Bumi, and Kya can fly
into the spirit portal on Oogi
when you see an opening.
- Let's get moving.
- What are we still doing here, Father?
- The invasion
was completely successful,
and the Southern Tribe
is under our control.
The spirit portals are open.
- You've restored balance.
Now we would like to go home.
- You don't understand.
Everything I've achieved so far
will pale in comparison
with what I'm about to accomplish.
- What else is there?
The Water Tribe is united.
- After today,
there will be no more Water Tribe,
no more nations of any kind.
The world is about to be transformed
into something magnificent and new,
and I will lead
this glorious revolution.
Now go outside
and get the troops ready
to defend the spirit portal.
- From whom?
We've already beaten everyone.
- The Avatar will be here soon.
She has no choice.
- Are you ready?
- I'm an Earthbender
strapped to the wing of a plane
hundreds of feet in the air, so no.
- Don't worry. There's no way
they'll be expecting this.
- I think they were expecting it.
Asami!
- Get ready.
Fire!
- There are spirits everywhere.
I don't see an opening.
- Let's circle around
and see if we can find a way in
from the other side.
Hold on!
The spirits are weighing Oogi down.
We're losing altitude.
- Get off of him,
you sticky, nasty, little blob of goo!
Whoa!
If I go, you're coming with me.
Aah!
- Bumi!
- I wish Varrick was filming this.
We could call it
"Nuktuk: Sky Warrior."
- Brace yourselves.
Dad.
- Korra, I'm so sorry.
I failed you.
- Don't give up.
Harmonic convergence isn't here yet.
We still have a chance.
- We tried.
- Congratulations, everyone.
You've all got front-row seats
for the beginning
of the new world order.
- You don't know
what you're doing, Unalaq.
Freeing Vaatu won't make you powerful.
It will only make you a traitor
to everything good
that's happened
for the last 10,000 years.
- You think what Avatar Wan
did was good?
Driving almost all the spirits
from this world?
The Avatar hasn't brought
balance, only chaos.
You call yourself the bridge
between the two worlds,
but there shouldn't be a bridge.
We should live together as one.
- Even if Vaatu escapes,
I'll put him right back
in his prison,
just like Wan did.
- It's true that,
when Wan fused with Raava,
he tipped the scales in her favor.
But this time,
I'll be here to level the playing field.
When harmonic convergence comes,
I will fuse with Vaatu.
And together,
we will become the new Avatar.
A Dark Avatar.
Your era is over.
- Think about what you're doing.
I know that you've always had
a deep connection
with the spirits,
but you're still a man.
You're still my brother.
You're Eska and Desna's father.
Are you willing
to throw your humanity away
to become a monster?
- I'll be no more of a monster
than your own daughter.
The only difference is that,
while she can barely recognize
her own spiritual power,
I will be in complete alignment
with mine.
Vaatu and I will be as one.
No one will be able
to stand against us.
Keep them locked up.
After the harmonic convergence,
I will come for Korra.
- Yes, Father.
- I failed in every way.
We've lost Jinora forever.
- There's still a chance.
They didn't get Bumi.
Oh, you want to play some more.
Well, bring it on.
Oh, we're playing dirty, huh?
Hmm, looks like we've got
a music lover here.
Reinforcements!
All right, soldiers.
Looks like it's on us to save the day.
Luckily, I've got a plan.
- Eska, Desna, listen to me.
You've got to help us stop Unalaq.
I know he's your father,
but Vaatu has made him
completely crazy.
- We will never turn on our father.
- Please, if you let me out now,
I can still stop him
from destroying everything.
Once he fuses with Vaatu,
no one will be safe.
Desna, he won't be
your father anymore.
- You don't know
what you're talking about.
Our father is the wisest man
in the world.
If he says what he is doing is right,
I believe him.
- Huh?
- You know, if I wanted
some ball of evil
lurking over my shoulder all the time,
I'd have stayed home
with my mother-in-law.
- All right, spirit army,
your general is here.
Follow me!
It's working.
It's not working.
Get me out of here!
Whoo-hoo!
- Aah!
- All right, guys.
Rescue time.
- Bumi, how did you manage to
take out this entire encampment
on your own?
- I did it all
with my trusty flute and--
oh, never mind.
You wouldn't believe it anyway.
Let's get moving.
- You run into the portal.
I'll try to hold off anyone
who comes after you.
- No, you're too hurt.
You need a healer.
Asami, can you take Oogi
and my dad back to my mom?
- Mm-hmm.
- This is my fight now.
- Korra.
I love you.
- I love you too, Dad.
. Yip-yip-
- Once we're inside, you go find Jinora.
Mako and Bolin will take care of Unalaq
while I close the portal,
so Vaatu can't escape.
- Wait a second.
Worst-case scenario.
So we're fighting Unalaq,
you close the portals,
and let's just say
something happens to you.
Are we gonna be trapped
in there for eternity?
- If everything goes as planned,
we'll all walk out together
after harmonic convergence.
If not...
Let's go.
Tenzin, go find Jinora.
- Come on!
- You're running out of time, Raava.
I know you feel it coming.