- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[epic music]
♪ ♪
- THE WORLD HAS ENTERED
A NEW AGE.
HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
CREATED AN ENERGY SHIFT
THE LIKES OF WHICH
HAS NEVER BEEN FELT BEFORE.
AND AFTER TWO WEEKS,
REPUBLIC CITY CONTINUES
TO RECOVER
FROM KORRA'S EPIC BATTLE
WITH UNAVAATU.
VINES HAVE SPROUTED UP
ALL OVER,
CREATING POCKETS OF WILDS
THE SPIRITS HAVE COME
TO CALL HOME.
WHAT OTHER CHANGES ARE IN STORE
FOR OUR CITY?
[serene music]
♪ ♪
- [chirping]
- COME BACK, BUM-JU.
- [chirps]
- [panting]
- IF YOU DON'T WANNA WEAR
THE SWEATER I MADE YOU,
THAT'S FINE.
I'M SORRY I GOT MAD.
[grunting]
BUM-JU,
I'M RUNNING OUT OF TREE.
CAN WE GO DOWN NOW?
[yells]
BUM-JU, A LITTLE HELP?
- [chirps]
- AH! AHH!
[screaming]
- [chirping]
- LOOK!
I'M AIRBENDING.
AH!
WOW, THAT STILL HURT A LOT.
- HOW ARE WE EVER GONNA
CLEAR AWAY ALL THESE VINES?
[scoffs]
I DON'T GET IT!
I CAN VANQUISH VAATU,
BUT NOT A BUNCH OF STUPID VINES?
- I'M SURE
YOU'LL FIND A WAY.
- WHY DO YOU WANNA
GET RID OF THEM?
YOU CHANGED THE WORLD.
WE'RE CONNECTED
WITH THE SPIRITS AGAIN.
THE WILDS ARE THEIR HOME.
- I DON'T THINK THE PEOPLE
WHO USED TO LIVE HERE
ARE AS EXCITED ABOUT IT
AS YOU ARE.
I GOTTA GO FACE THE PRESS
AND TELL THEM
I STILL DON'T HAVE A WAY
TO GET RID OF THE VINES.
THIS SHOULD BE FUN.
- MR. PRESIDENT,
ARE YOU CONCERNED
THAT YOUR APPROVAL RATINGS
ARE NOW NEARLY AS LOW
AS THE AVATAR'S?
- HAVE YOU SEEN
TODAY'S HEADLINE?
IT SAYS, "RAIK-OH-NO.
POLLS PAN PREZ PLANS!"
- I'M NOT CONCERNED WITH
SNAPPY PUT-DOWNS IN THE PRESS.
I'M FACING THIS CALAMITY
JUST LIKE EVERY OTHER CITIZEN.
THERE'S A TREE GROWING
RIGHT THROUGH MY OFFICE.
YOU THINK I'M NOT DOING
EVERYTHING I CAN
TO GET RID OF IT?
[wind gusts, crowd murmurs]
- A FEW QUESTIONS, PLEASE!
- AVATAR KORRA!
DO YOU REGRET THE WAY
YOU HANDLED THE UNALAQ CRISIS?
- WHY ARE YOU FORCING
THE INTEGRATION OF SPIRITS
IN REPUBLIC CITY?
- LISTEN, I'VE BEEN TRYING
EVERYTHING I CAN THINK OF
TO GET RID OF THESE VINES,
BUT--
- WHY CAN'T YOU FIX THIS?
- ARE THE VINES HERE TO STAY?
- IS THIS PART OF
YOUR NEW WORLD ORDER?
- LOOK!
HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
WAS JUST A COUPLE WEEKS AGO.
I JUST NEED
A LITTLE MORE TIME
TO GET EVERYTHING
BACK TO NORMAL.
- THE AVATAR HAS PUT US ALL
IN A VERY DIFFICULT POSITION,
BUT MY ADMINISTRATION--
- OH!
I'M SORRY.
DID I PUT YOU
IN A DIFFICULT POSITION
BY FIGHTING THE GIANT FORCE
OF PURE EVIL
THAT WAS GOING TO DESTROY
THE WHOLE WORLD?
MAYBE YOUR ADMINISTRATION
COULD'VE HANDLED THAT!
- THAT'S ALL!
NO MORE QUESTIONS!
[crowd murmurs]
[door opening]
- THIS IS A DISASTER.
- DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL FIGURE SOMETHING OUT.
- EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
YOU DON'T HAVE
MY POLL NUMBERS.
8% APPROVAL?
WHO WERE THEY ASKING?
- YOU CAN'T TAKE THAT
TO HEART.
PEOPLE ARE JUST FRUSTRATED.
- I DON'T BLAME THEM.
I SHOULD BE ABLE
TO FIX THIS.
I'M THE AVATAR.
- [panting]
YOU ARE NOT GONNA BELIEVE
WHAT JUST HAPPENED.
WHERE'S YOUR FATHER?
- DAD!
- WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S WRONG?
- THE MOST AMAZING, WONDROUS,
FANTASTICAL THING JUST OCCURRED.
OKAY, BUM-JU AND I HAD A LITTLE
FIGHT. I MADE HIM THIS SWEATER,
AND HE DIDN'T SEEM TO LIKE IT.
AND I'LL ADMIT
IT MIGHT NEED WORK,
BUT IT WAS MY FIRST ATTEMPT
AT KNITTING.
SO I WAS A LITTLE HURT.
- HILARIOUS.
TIME FOR DINNER, EVERYONE.
- NO! CHECK THIS OUT.
I CAN AIRBEND!
[strained grunts]
YEAH, WAIT.
SERIOUSLY. I WAS DOING IT.
[straining]
OH, HOLD ON.
I JUST...
MAYBE IF I...
[grunts]
NO.
I SWEAR I'M NOT MAKING IT UP.
[grunting]
- STOP WAVING YOUR ARMS AROUND
AT THE TABLE.
IT'S NOT FUNNY ANYMORE.
- IT'S NOT A JOKE.
- WHAT'S UP WITH HIM?
- BUMI SAYS
HE AIRBENDED EARLIER,
BUT HE CAN'T NOW.
OH, AND I GUESS HE'S NOT
VERY GOOD AT KNITTING EITHER.
I GOTTA SAY, I LOVE
BEING A PART OF THIS FAMILY.
YOU GOT THE GRUMPY DAD,
THE WACKY UNCLE.
THE PUT-UPON MOM,
CRAZY KIDS.
THIS IS GREAT.
- WHERE'S MAKO?
- OH, YOU MEAN
THE BROODING TEENAGER?
HE'S STAYING
AT THE POLICE STATION.
- STILL?
- I TOLD HIM TENZIN INVITED US
TO STAY HERE
SINCE OUR APARTMENT
IS A VINE HABITAT NOW,
BUT HE SAID HE HAD TO
FOCUS ON WORK.
- [grunt]
OH!
DID YOU SEE THAT?
I THINK THE NAPKIN MOVED.
- YOU BLEW ON IT.
- WAIT!
MAYBE I CAN ONLY DO IT
WHEN MY LIFE IS IN DANGER.
BOLIN, BEND A GIANT BOULDER
AT ME.
- YEAH, I DON'T THINK
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
- IF YOU'RE GONNA BE BENDING
GIANT BOULDERS,
YOU CAN DO IT OUTSIDE.
- NO ONE IS BENDING
GIANT BOULDERS!
- LOOK ALIVE, UNCLE BUMI!
- AH!
I TOLD YOU!
- UNBELIEVABLE.
YOU'RE ACTUALLY AN AIRBENDER.
- WAIT UNTIL I TELL MOM.
SHE'S GONNA LOVE THIS.
[plate breaks]
[phone ringing]
- OW!
POLICE.
HE WHAT?
SLOW DOWN.
OKAY, I'M ON MY WAY.
WHAT THE HECK DID ALL THIS?
- IT WAS MY BROTHER.
HE'S OUT OF CONTROL!
- OKAY, JUST TELL ME
WHAT HAPPENED.
- WE WERE ARGUING
ABOUT THE BOOKS,
AND DAW WAS YELLING AT ME,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN
THINGS STARTED FLYING AROUND!
HE WAS CREATING THIS STORM
LIKE...
- LIKE WHAT?
- WELL,
LIKE HE WAS AIRBENDING.
- SIR...
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE ARE ONLY FIVE AIRBENDERS
IN THE ENTIRE WORLD,
AND YOUR BROTHER
IS NOT ONE OF THEM.
- I KNOW WHAT I SAW.
HE WAS FREAKING OUT, YELLING,
"WHAT HAPPENING TO ME?"
THEN, HE RAN
INTO THE BACK ROOM
AND LOCKED HIMSELF IN.
- POLICE. OPEN UP.
- GO AWAY!
- GET OUT HERE, SIR,
OR I'M KNOCKING THIS DOOR DOWN.
ONE...
TWO...
[grunts]
- AH!
I'M SO SORRY!
[yelling]
- I TOLD YOU!
AIRBENDING!
- [groans]
- [grunting]
UGH!
I CAN'T FIGURE THIS THING OUT!
- DO YOU THINK BEING
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD
DURING HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
COULD'VE GIVEN HIM BENDING?
- I SUPPOSED IT'S POSSIBLE.
- MAYBE UNCLE BUMI
IS JUST A LATE BLOOMER.
- I HAVE BEEN NOTICING
A CHANGE IN YOUR AURA LATELY.
- AND YOU DIDN'T TELL ME?
[grunting]
- INVISIBLE
SPIRIT MONSTER ATTACK?
- LIN! YOU WON'T BELIEVE THIS.
BUMI JUST STARTED AIRBENDING.
- I'M AFRAID
HE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE.
all: WHAT?
- I GOT A CALL LAST NIGHT
ABOUT A GUY WHO JUST STARTED
AIRBENDING OUT OF NOWHERE.
- YOU MEAN THERE'S ANOTHER ONE?
WHERE IS HE NOW?
- HE...BLEW A DOOR DOWN ON ME
AND GOT AWAY.
WE'VE GOT AN ALL-POINTS BULLETIN
OUT ON HIM RIGHT NOW.
- WAIT, WE'LL HELP YOU
LOOK FOR HIM.
WHERE SHOULD WE START?
- OH, WELL, YOU KNOW,
YOU SHOULD...
YOU SHOULD LEAVE IT
TO THE POLICE.
IT'S...POLICE BUSINESS,
YOU KNOW.
IT'S, UM...OFFICIAL.
- OKAY.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
YOU KNOW YOU'RE WELCOME
TO STAY HERE
INSTEAD OF SLEEPING
AT THE POLICE STATION.
- NO, I'M FINE.
I SHOULD JUST GET...GOING.
- SO!
AS YOU WERE...
LADIES.
- THIS IS SO EXCITING!
NEW AIRBENDERS IN THE CITY?
I BET WE CAN FIND THAT GUY
BEFORE MAKO DOES.
YOU KNOW
I'M NOT VERY GOOD AT THIS.
- YOU'RE THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL THE ELEMENTS.
YOU SHOULD KNOW
HOW TO DRIVE.
BESIDES, IT'S RELAXING.
[tires screeching]
CLUTCH! CLUTCH!
UGH! AH! UGH!
[horn honking,
tires screeching]
THAT'S THE BRAKE.
LET'S TRY AGAIN.
YOU READY?
[ahooga horn honking]
[laughter]
- HOW LONG DO YOU THINK
TALKING TO MAKO
IS GOING TO BE
LIKE PULLING TEETH?
- WELL, MAKO HAS NEVER BEEN
THE MOST "IN TOUCH
WITH HIS FEELINGS" GUY.
BUT IT'LL GET BETTER
EVENTUALLY.
- SO WHEN I WAS GONE,
DID HE TELL YOU
THAT WE BROKE UP?
- YEAH. WE ALL KNEW.
SORRY.
- THAT'S PRETTY EMBARRASSING.
- ACTUALLY, I NEED TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT,
AND I SHOULD'VE
TOLD YOU THIS SOONER,
BUT...WHILE YOU WERE GONE,
I...KIND OF...KISSED HIM.
I'M SORRY.
- [laughing]
NO WONDER HE'S SO NERVOUS
AROUND US.
- YOU'RE NOT MAD?
- NO!
I MEAN, I KISSED MAKO WHEN
HE WAS GOING OUT WITH YOU, SO.
- YOU WHAT?
- I'M SO SORRY!
I THOUGHT YOU KNEW!
- I'M JUST KIDDING.
I KNEW A LONG TIME AGO.
- [laughing]
WELL, WHATEVER HAPPENED
WITH MAKO
I'M GLAD
IT HASN'T COME BETWEEN US.
I'VE NEVER HAD A GIRLFRIEND
TO HANG OUT WITH
AND TALK TO BEFORE,
EXCEPT FOR NAGA.
THIS IS NICE.
- VINE! VINE!
[both screaming]
[gasps]
- HEY!
WATCH WHERE YOU'RE GOING!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
LIVING IN THE MIDDLE OF THE ROAD
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
- DON'T ASK ME, AVATAR.
YOU MADE THE WORLD
THIS WAY.
WE'RE JUST LIVING IN IT.
- LOOK, I DON'T HAVE ANYTHING
AGAINST SPIRITS,
BUT THESE VINES
ARE CAUSING MAJOR PROBLEMS
ALL OVER THE CITY.
- SPIRITS? VINES?
WE'RE ALL THE SAME.
SEEMS LIKE THE AVATAR
WOULD KNOW THAT.
- KORRA, YOU OKAY?
- I THINK THAT SPIRIT
JUST GAVE ME AN IDEA
HOW TO GET RID
OF THESE VINES.
BUT I'M GONNA NEED
A LOT OF WATER.
- IT'S LIKE A DREAM, DAD.
AFTER 170 YEARS,
NEW AIRBENDERS.
- DAD?
WHEN A NEW GUY
GETS AIRBENDING,
DOES THAT MAKE HIM
OUR BROTHER?
- WELL, IN A WAY,
ALL AIRBENDERS ARE OUR FAMILY.
- DOES THAT MEAN
I HAVE TO SHARE MY ROOM?
BECAUSE I LIKE
MY PERSONAL SPACE.
- OF COURSE NOT.
BUT WE MIGHT HAVE
TO GET USED
TO NOT BEING THE ONLY AIRBENDERS
AROUND ANY MORE.
- I HOPE WE HAVE ENOUGH
FOR AN ARMY.
I WANNA BE A COMMANDER
LIKE UNCLE BUMI.
- AIR NOMADS DON'T HAVE ARMIES,
MEELO.
- BUT MAYBE THERE WILL BE ENOUGH
TO FILL THE TEMPLES AGAIN.
- WHAT'S WRONG, DADDY?
- I JUST WISH YOUR GRANDFATHER
WERE HERE TO SEE THIS.
- WILL YOU BE
AIRBENDER PRESIDENT?
- NO.
BUT I THINK
THE NEW AIRBENDERS
WILL NEED LOTS OF HELP
AND GUIDANCE
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE A PART OF OUR NATION.
THAT'S A BIG RESPONSIBILITY
- DON'T WORRY, DAD.
WE'LL HELP YOU.
- I KNOW YOU WILL.
- I HOPE THIS WORKS.
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
DOING HERE?
- I WAS ALERTED
THAT YOU HAD A NEW PLAN
TO WIPE OUT
THESE NOXIOUS WEEDS,
SO I THOUGHT YOU'D WANT
EVERYONE TO BE HERE TO WATCH.
- AVATAR KORRA!
DO YOU REALLY THINK--
- NO QUESTIONS!
JUST STAND THERE.
SILENTLY!
[serene music]
♪ ♪
GO IN PEACE.
[sighs]
- HOW DID YOU KNOW
WHAT TO DO?
WILL YOU SEND THE SPIRITS
AWAY NOW?
- HOW SOON CAN WE EXPECT
PUBLIC WATER SERVICE TO RESUME?
- LOOK OUT!
[all screaming]
LET'S GO, PEOPLE.
HURRY!
[all yelling]
[gasps]
HANG ON!
- I THINK THAT
COULD'VE GONE BETTER.
- CAN'T TALK.
MEDITATING.
- YOU MUST BE
AT THE END OF YOUR ROPE.
YOU HATE MEDITATING.
- I THOUGHT THAT
IF I REALLY TRIED
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO CONTACT
MY PAST AVATARS,
SOMEONE WHO KNOWS SOMETHING
TO HELP ME.
BUT I CAN'T.
THEY'RE GONE,
AND I'M ALL ALONE.
DID I RUIN EVERYTHING BY LEAVING
THE SPRIT PORTALS OPEN?
- YOU DIDN'T RUIN ANYTHING.
YOU DID WHAT YOU THOUGHT
WAS BEST FOR THE WORLD,
AND NOW THINGS HAVE CHANGED.
CHANGE CAN BE GOOD OR BAD.
DEPENDING
ON YOUR POINT OF VIEW.
- [sighs]
I KNOW THE PEOPLE'S
POINT OF VIEW.
IT'S BAD.
- YOU'RE NOT THE PRESIDENT,
KORRA.
YOUR JOB ISN'T TO FIX
THE DAILY PROBLEMS
OF EVERY PERSON
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY
IS TO BRING BALANCE
TO THE ENTIRE WORLD.
AND THAT MEANS
NO MATTER WHAT YOU DO,
SOME PEOPLE ARE NOT GOING
TO BE HAPPY ABOUT IT.
- GREAT.
- ON THE OTHER HAND,
SOME PEOPLE WILL BE VERY HAPPY.
LIKE ME.
WHAT YOU DID
DURING HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
MAY HAVE BROUGHT BACK
THE AIR NATION.
AND THAT CAN ONLY BE GOOD
FOR RESTORING BALANCE.
THAT IS THE ACT
OF A GREAT AVATAR.
- IT'S SCARY.
I HAVE ALL THIS POWER AND ALL
THESE PEOPLE DEPENDING ON ME,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'M SUPPOSED TO BE DOING
HALF THE TIME.
IT SEEMS LIKE I SHOULD BE...
WISER.
- TRUE WISDOM BEGINS WHEN
WE ACCEPT THINGS AS THEY ARE.
YOU STARTED A NEW AGE,
KORRA.
THERE'S NO GOING BACK
TO THE PAST.
- MAKO CALLED!
THE COPS FOUND
THE NEW AIRBENDER GUY.
BUT WHEN THEY TRIED
TO BRING HIM IN,
HE RAN AWAY AND CLIMBED
TO THE TOP OF KYOSHI BRIDGE
AND HE WON'T COME DOWN.
OOH! SORRY.
DID I INTERRUPT
AN AVATAR WISDOM SESSION?
- AVATAR WISDOM'S
A THING OF THE PAST, BOLIN.
COME ON!
- OH, OKAY.
IS THAT A GOOD THING?
- DEPENDS WHO YOU ASK.
- [growls]
- COME DOWN IMMEDIATELY,
OR WE WILL BE FORCED
TO TAKE ACTION.
- [panting]
STAY BACK!
I'M DANGEROUS!
[whimpering]
[screams]
SORRY!
- DON'T PANIC,
I'M JUST HERE TO TALK.
- PLEASE!
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M DOING,
AND I DON'T WANNA HURT ANYONE.
- TELL ME ABOUT IT.
ROUGH DAY, HUH?
I'M HAVING
KIND OF A ROUGH DAY MYSELF.
YOU MIND IF I SIT DOWN HERE?
- [whimpering]
- LOOK,
I KNOW YOU'RE SCARED.
YOU'VE GONE THROUGH
A BIG CHANGE,
AND IT'S KIND OF MY FAULT.
BUT YOU'RE NOT ALONE.
THERE ARE OTHER AIRBENDERS
AND THEY WANNA HELP YOU.
ACTUALLY THEY'RE REALLY
EXCITED TO MEET YOU.
- I DON'T WANNA BE
AN AIRBENDER.
PLEASE! YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
MAKE IT STOP!
[yells]
- I'M SORRY, I CAN'T.
BUT I PROMISE YOU
THINGS WILL GET BETTER
IF YOU JUST GIVE IT A CHANCE.
LET ME TAKE YOU
OVER TO AIR TEMPLE ISLAND
AND WE CAN TALK THIS THROUGH,
OKAY?
- [screaming]
[crowd cheering]
- DAW, THIS IS TENZIN.
HE'S GOING TO HELP YOU.
- IT IS ABSOLUTELY MY PLEASURE
TO MEET YOU, DAW.
I'VE NEVER MET
A NEW AIRBENDER BEFORE.
WELL, AT LEAST NO ONE
WHOSE DIAPER
I DIDN'T HAVE TO CHANGE.
- ACTUALLY I JUST FELL
OFF A BRIDGE,
SO I COULD USE A FRESH DIAPER
RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
- SO IS THIS THE DEAL?
WE HAVE A CRISIS
EVERY OTHER DAY NOW,
THANKS TO YOU?
- LISTEN, I KNOW
YOU'RE HAVING A TOUGH TIME
GETTING USED
TO THESE CHANGES,
AND I'M SORRY FOR THAT.
BUT YOU AND EVERYONE ELSE
ARE GONNA HAVE TO LEARN
TO LIVE WITH IT.
THE VINES AND THE SPIRITS
ARE HERE TO STAY.
- WELL, YOU KNOW
WHO'S NOT HERE TO SAY? YOU!
I ORDER YOU
TO LEAVE THIS CITY.
YOU'VE CAUSED NOTHING
BUT TROUBLE SINCE YOU ARRIVED.
[crowd gasps]
- DON'T WORRY.
I WAS ALREADY LEAVING.
I CAN SEE MY PATH NOW.
THERE ARE NEW AIRBENDERS
OUT THERE,
AND I'M GONNA FIND THEM
AND REBUILD THE AIR NATION.
- DON'T THINK
I'M NOT GOING WITH YOU.
IT'S SO EXCITING.
WHO KNOWS
WHO'S OUT THERE RIGHT NOW,
DISCOVERING THE GIFT OF
AIRBENDING FOR THE FIRST TIME?
[rumbling]
- YOU KNOW THE DRILL, ZAHEER.
- OF COURSE.
- HOPE YOU STILL LIKE RICE.
- HAVE YOU EVER READ
THE POETRY
OF THE GREAT AIRBENDING GURU
LAGHIMA?
- WHAT?
- GURU LAGHIMA
LIVED 4,000 YEARS AGO
IN THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
IT IS SAID THAT HE UNLOCKED
THE SECRET OF WEIGHTLESSNESS
AND BECAME UNTETHERED
FROM THE EARTH,
LIVING HIS FINAL 40 YEARS
WITHOUT EVER TOUCHING
THE GROUND.
- IS THAT HOW YOU PLAN
TO ESCAPE,
WITH SOMETHING YOU PICKED UP
FROM AN OLD AIRBENDER
CHILDREN'S STORY?
- LIKE ALL GREAT
CHILDREN'S TALES,
IT CONTAINS TRUTH
WITHIN THE MYTH.
LAGHIMA ONCE WROTE,
"INSTINCT IS A LIE
TOLD BY A FEARFUL BODY,
HOPING TO BE WRONG."
- WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- IT MEANS THAT WHEN YOU BASE
YOUR EXPECTATIONS
ONLY ON WHAT YOU SEE,
YOU BLIND YOURSELF
TO THE POSSIBILITIES
OF A NEW REALITY.
- UGH!
- AH, AH, AH.
YOU WOULDN'T WANNA
SINGE YOUR FRIEND, WOULD YOU?
- HOW?
YOU'RE NOT A BENDER!
- NATURE IS CONSTANTLY CHANGING,
LIKE THE WIND.
- [grunts]
- NOW YOU MIGHT WANNA RATION
THAT BOWL OF RICE.
YOU'VE GOT THREE WEEKS
UNTIL THE NEXT SHIFT CHANGE.
IT'S THE DAWNING OF A NEW AGE,
THE END OF THE WHITE LOTUS,
AND SOON,
THE END OF THE AVATAR.