- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
- AFTER 170 YEARS,
THERE ARE NEW AIRBENDERS
IN THE WORLD,
AND BUMI IS ONE OF THEM.
SO TOO IS
THE MYSTERIOUS ZAHEER,
WHO ESCAPED FROM
HIS REMOTE PRISON
THANKS TO HIS NEW ABILITY.
NOW EXILED FROM REPUBLIC CITY,
KORRA HAS MADE IT
HER MISSION
TO FIND
ALL THE NEW AIRBENDERS.
BUT WILL SHE AND TENZIN
BE ABLE TO BRING BACK
THE AIR NATION?
- DID SOMEONE ORDER
A FULLY-EQUIPPED
FUTURE INDUSTRIES AIRSHIP?
- IT'S PERFECT.
THANKS, ASAMI.
- I FIGURED IF WE'RE GOING
TO BA SING SE
TO SEARCH FOR AIRBENDERS,
WE SHOULD DO IT IN STYLE.
- YAY! AIRSHIP!
- I WANNA SEE.
- COME ON, POKI.
- WHILE YOU GUYS ARE GONE,
PEMA AND I WILL HOLD DOWN
THE FORT.
WHO'S EXCITED TO SPEND
SOME TIME
WITH YOUR AUNTIE KYA?
OH.
- AWW. HE LIKES YOU.
- MAKO,
I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
- OF COURSE, KORRA.
AVATAR--
AVATAR KORRA.
ONCE I RECEIVED YOUR MESSAGE,
I PROCEEDED TO CONTACT
VARIOUS LOCATIONS
WITHIN THE EARTH KINGDOM
AS ORDERED BY YOU,
THE AVATAR.
- RIGHT.
THE AVATAR THANKS YOU
FOR YOUR LOYAL SERVICE.
DID YOU FIND ANY MORE LEADS?
- THERE ARE REPORTS
OF AIRBENDERS
POPPING UP ALL OVER
THE EARTH KINGDOM.
I MARKED THE VILLAGES
ON THIS MAP.
YOU GUYS CAN TAKE IT WITH YOU.
- ACTUALLY, I WAS KIND OF HOPING
YOU COULD COME TOO.
- REALLY?
UM, IT'S PROBABLY BETTER
IF I SIT THIS ONE OUT.
- I KNOW THINGS HAVE BEEN WEIRD
BETWEEN US
SINCE WE BROKE UP, BUT
YOU'RE A PART OF TEAM AVATAR
AND WE CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
- I'M SORRY, I CAN'T.
- I'LL MISS YOU, SWEETIE.
[kisses]
- I'LL MISS YOU TOO.
ONCE WE FIND THE AIRBENDERS,
I'LL SEND WORD.
YOU CAN JOIN US
AT THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE THEN.
- HEY! HOW COME JINORA GETS
TO GO WITH YOU BUT WE DON'T?
THAT'S SO NOT FAIR.
- YEAH, WHAT THIS GIRL SAID.
NOT FAIR.
- BECAUSE IF AIRBENDERS
SHOW UP HERE,
THEY'RE GOING TO NEED
SOME GUIDANCE FROM YOU TWO.
IT'S A VERY IMPORTANT JOB.
- REALLY?
ME, A TEACHER?
YAY!
- THOSE MAGGOTS WILL BOW TO ME.
- GO EASY ON THEM, SON.
- MAKO, WAIT A SEC.
- KORRA ALREADY ASKED, BRO.
I CAN'T JUST LEAVE
REPUBLIC CITY.
I HAVE A LIFE HERE
AND A JOB.
- A LIFE? YOU SLEEP UNDER
YOUR DESK.
AND WHAT'S
A MORE IMPORTANT JOB
THAN HELPING THE AVATAR REBUILD
AN ENTIRE CIVILIZATION?
- IT'S NOT JUST THAT.
I FEEL LIKE I'VE BEEN
DRIFTING APART FROM EVERYONE.
- WELL, DRIFT BACK.
WE NEED YOU!
COME ON, MAKO,
WE'RE GOING TO BA SING SE
WHERE DAD GREW UP.
WHAT IF I MEET OUR GRANDMA
FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME?
AND SHE ASKS ME,
"WHERE'S YOUR SWEET BROTHER?"
AND I HAVE TO SAY,
"I'M SORRY, GRANDMA.
HE HAD SOME REALLY IMPORTANT
POLICE PAPERWORK TO FILE."
AND SHE STARTS TO CRY
THOSE GRANDMA TEARS
AND IS LIKE, "MAKO! WHY?
WHY, MAKO?
I CAN'T GO ON.
I CAN'T--"
AND THEN SHE DIES.
- OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
[sighs]
I GUESS I GOTTA CALL BEIFONG.
SHE'S NOT GOING
TO BE HAPPY.
- BYE.
WE'LL MISS YOU.
[Naga pants]
- AS OF NOW,
THESE ARE
THE TOWNS WHERE
WE'VE GOTTEN REPORTS
ABOUT AIRBENDERS.
IT LOOKS LIKE WE CAN HIT UP
MOST OF THEM
BEFORE WE GET TO BA SING SE.
- WE'RE GOING TO BRING
THE AIR NATION
BACK FROM THE BRINK
OF EXTINCTION
AFTER NEARLY 200 YEARS.
- AND IT'S ALL
BECAUSE OF YOU, KORRA.
[wood creaks]
- FINALLY, OUR SHIFT CHANGE
IS HERE.
- HEY, WHERE ARE
THE OTHER GUARDS?
ZAHEER?
[men groaning]
- [groans]
[men groan]
- AAH!
- IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
GHAZAN.
- THANKS FOR BUSTING ME OUT.
WHERE'D YOU PICK UP
THE NEW SKILLS?
- I HAVE HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
TO THANK FOR THAT.
I WAS GIVEN A GIFT.
I BELIEVE IT'S A SIGN THAT
OUR PATH IS A RIGHTEOUS ONE.
- AVATAR KORRA,
OH, IT IS SUCH AN HONOR
TO HAVE YOU COME
TO OUR HUMBLE VILLAGE.
- THANKS.
- I HATE TO GET DOWN TO
BUSINESS, BUT IS THE AIRBENDER
HERE NOW?
- KUON AND HIS FAMILY WILL BE
JOINING US SHORTLY
FOR A SPECIAL DINNER.
PLEASE, RIGHT THIS WAY.
KUON HAS BEEN THE TALK
OF THE TOWN
EVER SINCE HE GOT AIRBENDING.
HE'S LIKE A LOCAL CELEBRITY.
- I JUST WANT TO SAY
THAT IT'S AN HONOR
TO MEET
A FELLOW AIRBENDER.
- OH, I STILL JUST THINK
OF MYSELF
AS A SIMPLE FARMER...
WHO CAN AIRBEND.
OH, I'M SO SORRY.
I STILL DON'T HAVE
ANY CONTROL.
- NO WORRIES.
I LOVE PIE.
AND SO DOES PABU.
- WELL, YOU'RE SO MUCH MORE
THAN JUST A FARMER NOW.
HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
CHANGED EVERYTHING.
YOU REPRESENT THE FUTURE
OF A CULTURE
THAT IS BEING REBORN.
YOU'RE GOING TO HELP US
REBUILD THE AIR NATION.
- I'M GONNA DO WHAT NOW?
THE ONLY THING I'M PLANNING
TO REBUILD IS MY BARN.
- BUT YOU MUST COME WITH US
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
- WELL, I CAN'T DO THAT.
I HAVE A FAMILY AND A FARM.
- OF COURSE YOU CAN COME.
THIS IS OF
THE UTMOST IMPORTANCE!
YOUR WIFE WILL UNDERSTAND.
- WAIT, WHAT?
NO, I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
- DADDY, WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
WHY DOES THE BALD MAN
WANT TO TAKE YOU AWAY?
- NO ONE'S GOING TO TAKE
DADDY AWAY, SWEETHEART.
- ACTUALLY, THIS BALD MAN
DOES WANT TO TAKE HIM,
BUT IT'S FOR
AN IMPORTANT CAUSE.
YOUR DAD IS AN AIRBENDER,
AND HE SHOULD LEARN
ABOUT HIS CULTURE.
- I THINK THERE'S BEEN
SOME SORT OF MISUNDERSTANDING.
I'M NOT GOING WITH YOU.
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO AIRBEND,
BUT I'M NO AIR NOMAD!
I'M NO MONK!
- OKAY, UH, MAYBE WE SHOULD
JUST HAVE SOME DESSERT, HUH?
WHO'S UP FOR DESSERT?
- SIR, YOU MUST UNDERSTAND,
YOU'RE AN AIRBENDER NOW,
AND THERE ARE THOUSANDS
OF YEARS OF CULTURE
YOU MUST LEARN ABOUT.
SKILLS YOU MUST MASTER.
- YOU EXPECT ME TO ABANDON
MY ENTIRE LIFE? MY FAMILY?
NO! NO, SIR!
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE
WITH YOU
AND I THINK IT'S BEST
THAT YOU LEAVE!
- IN MY HEAD I SAW THAT
PLAYING OUT VERY DIFFERENTLY.
- MAYBE WE SHOULD HAVE STAYED
AND TRIED HARDER
TO CONVINCE HIM TO JOIN US.
- OR WE COULD'VE THROWN HIM
INTO A POTATO SACK
AND FORCED HIM INTO THE SHIP.
- THAT'S HOW THEY GOT ME
TO JOIN THE UNITED FORCES.
- NO, WE CAN'T COERCE PEOPLE
OR THROW THEM IN POTATO SACKS.
THEY MUST COME FREELY.
BUT NOT TO WORRY,
THERE ARE PLENTY
OF OTHER AIRBENDERS OUT THERE
WHO WILL BE HAPPY TO COME
WITH US
ONCE THEY FIND OUT WHAT
THE AIR NATION'S ALL ABOUT.
WHEN YOUR SON BECOMES
A MASTER,
HE'LL GET TATTOOS ALL
OVER HIS BODY, JUST LIKE ME.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE NUTRITIOUS
THAN OUR VEGETARIAN DIET.
I CAN TELL THAT YOU'RE GOING
TO LOVE
WEARING
OUR ANCIENT AIRBENDER ROBES.
THEY'RE VERY BREATHABLE.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT YOUR
WORLDLY POSSESSIONS AGAIN
BECAUSE YOU WON'T HAVE ANY.
YOU'LL GET TO
SHAVE YOUR HEAD!
YOUR BEST FRIEND
WILL BE A GIANT BISON!
[Pabu chirps]
- [groans]
I REALLY THOUGHT
I HAD THAT LAST GUY.
WHO DOESN'T WANT A BISON
AS THEIR BEST FRIEND?
- IT'S OKAY, TENZIN.
I STILL WANT TO BE
AN AIRBENDER.
- OKAY, WE'VE TRIED IT YOUR WAY,
AND PEOPLE JUST DON'T
SEEM TO BE RESPONDING.
IT'S TIME FOR
A LITTLE TOUGH LOVE.
[knock on door]
- OH, ARE YOU THE AVATAR?
WHEN MY SON GOT AIRBENDING,
MY HUSBAND AND I
WERE SO HAPPY.
WE THOUGHT THIS COULD OPEN
A LOT OF DOORS FOR HIM.
AND MAYBE HE COULD FINALLY
MOVE OUT OF THE BASEMENT.
[both laugh]
- HOW OLD IS HE?
- HE'S 22,
AND, YOU KNOW,
STILL JUST FIGURING
HIS LIFE OUT.
- WELL, I HAVE
A GREAT OPPORTUNITY FOR HIM.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR AIRBENDERS
TO JOIN US
AT THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
- [squeals]
THAT SOUNDS WONDERFUL!
I'LL GET HIM.
RYU, GET UP HERE!
- HI, I'M KORRA.
- SO, YOU'RE LIKE THE AVATAR
OR SOMETHING? BIG DEAL.
- AH, I JUST WANTED TO TALK
TO YOU
ABOUT AN OPPORTUNITY--
- YEAH, I HEARD YOU TALKING
TO MY MOM,
AND I'M NOT INTERESTED.
- WELL, YOU'RE GONNA BE
INTERESTED!
YOU'RE AN AIRBENDER NOW,
AND YOU HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
AS A CITIZEN OF
THE WORLD.
- WHATEVER.
I DIDN'T ASK TO BECOME
AN AIRBENDER, YOU KNOW.
- WELL, I DIDN'T ASK
TO BE THE AVATAR,
BUT I AM, AND I'M FULFILLING
MY DUTIES.
- SO?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
- YES, I DO HAVE TO.
- NO, YOU DON'T.
- YES, I DO.
- WELL, IF I DIDN'T EMBRACE
MY ROLE,
THEN OUR ENTIRE WORLD
COULD BE THROWN INTO CHAOS.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
- MAYBE.
- NO, IT'S NOT!
- SO WHAT? WHO CARES?
- EVERYONE CARES!
- I DON'T CARE.
- YES, YOU DO!
- NO, I DON'T.
- WELL, YOU'RE ABOUT TO CARE,
YOU LITTLE SLACKER,
BECAUSE YOU'RE COMING
WITH ME!
- STOP PULLING ON MY COLLAR,
YOU'RE STRETCHING IT OUT.
MOM, ARE YOU JUST
GONNA JUST LET HER TAKE ME?
- I THINK IT'S
A GREAT OPPORTUNITY.
[laughs] JUST TRY IT FOR
A WEEK AND SEE HOW IT GOES.
- NO! LET ME GO!
- AAH!
[groans]
- THAT'S IT!
- KORRA, ENOUGH!
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
- SO NICE TO MEET YOU.
GOOD LUCK WITH YOUR SON.
- [groans]
- WE'RE UNDER ATTACK!
- LOOK OUT!
- AAH!
[men groan]
- OH!
- WHOA!
- [groans]
- I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D BE SO HAPPY
TO SEE YOUR UGLY MUGS AGAIN.
- GREAT TO SEE YOU TOO,
MING-HUA.
- I'M FLATTERED,
YOU BUSTED ME OUT
BEFORE THAT GIRLFRIEND OF YOURS.
- WE'RE GETTING HER NEXT.
- WELL, I GUESS WE SHOULD
JUST GO TO BA SING SE
AND TRY OUR LUCK THERE.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
I JUST THOUGHT MORE PEOPLE
WOULD BE EXCITED
ABOUT COMING WITH US.
- WELL, MAYBE YOU GOTTA
DO MORE TO GET THEM EXCITED.
YOU NEED TO ADD
A LITTLE RAZZLE DAZZLE.
- YEAH, RAZZLE DAZZLE.
WE COULD PUT ON SOME SORT OF
AIRBENDING STREET PERFORMANCE.
- I WAS GOING TO SAY WE COULD
COVER TENZIN'S ROBE IN SEQUINS,
BUT THAT'S EVEN BETTER.
- IT SOUNDS RIDICULOUS,
BUT IT MIGHT WORK.
- I'M WILLING TO TRY ANYTHING
AT THIS POINT.
- YES! THAT IS THE KIND
OF ENTHUSIASM I LIKE TO HEAR.
COME ONE, COME ALL AND WITNESS
THE AMAZING AIRBENDERS!
AN AIRBENDING SHOW THAT WILL
LEAVE YOU BREATHLESS WITH WIND!
FIRST UP,
THE TATTOOED MASTER HIMSELF.
YOU KNOW HIM AS THE SON
OF AVATAR AANG.
HE SHAVES EVERY HAIR
ON HIS HEAD,
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
IT'S THE ONE,
THE ONLY GUY
WITH AN ARROW POINTING
TO HIS NOSE--
TENZIN!
[crowd exclaims]
[all cheering]
NOW, NOW,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
PLEASE BE QUIET.
I HAVE SOME SERIOUS NEWS.
WE'VE HEARD THAT
AN ESCAPED FIREBENDING CONVICT
HAS BEEN SPOTTED NEAR HERE.
NOW, I DON'T WANT
TO PANIC ANYONE,
BUT IF YOU SEE A FIREBENDER
WITH A RED SCARF...
- I SEE HIM.
HE'S RIGHT THERE!
- [flatly]
I AM THE ESCAPED CONVICT,
AND YOU WILL ALL REAP MY FIRE.
[crowd gasping]
- OH, NO,
WHO WILL HELP US?
- I WILL!
WITH MY AIRBENDING SKILLS.
- WHOA! AAH!
OH! AAH! AAH!
HEY! LET ME GO!
THIS IS NOT WHAT
WE REHEARSED!
KORRA!
- [laughs]
- [chuckles]
- WITH THE POWER
OF AIRBENDING,
EVEN THIS BEAST CAN FLOAT
LIKE A FEATHER!
LOOK WHAT CAN BE DONE IN ONLY
A FEW SHORT WEEKS OF PRACTICE.
NO, NO, DON'T WORRY,
FOLKS,
SHE MIGHT BE YOUNG,
BUT SHE IS IN FULL CONTROL.
[applause]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IF YOU OR ANYONE YOU KNOW
IS AN AIRBENDER,
PLEASE SEND THEM OUR WAY.
MASTER TENZIN AND AVATAR KORRA
WOULD LOVE TO TEACH THEM
ALL THEY KNOW.
- HEY.
HELLO.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR AIRBENDERS,
YOU JUST FOUND ONE.
I WANT TO JOIN YOU GUYS.
- GET OUTTA TOWN!
- WE GOT OUR FIRST RECRUIT.
- JUST TO BE
TOTALLY CLEAR,
WE'RE GOING TO BE HEADING
TO BA SING SE,
THEN THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE
TO LIVE AS NOMADS
AND REBUILD THE AIR NATION.
ALL THAT SOUND GOOD TO YOU?
- YEAH, BA SING SE,
REBUILD THE TEMPLE,
AIR NOMAD WHADDYADO--
I'M IN.
LET'S GO RIGHT NOW.
- THIS IS GOING TO BE SO GREAT.
YOU ARE GONNA LOVE IT--
UH, AH--
REAL QUICK,
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
- KAI. SO WHEN DO WE HIT
THE ROAD?
- HANG ON A SECOND, KAI.
WHERE ARE YOUR PARENTS?
WE CAN'T HAVE YOU COME WITH US
WITHOUT THEIR PERMISSION.
- MY PARENTS ARE...GONE.
- YOU'RE AN ORPHAN?
- IT HAPPENED
ABOUT A YEAR AGO.
MY HOMETOWN WAS RAIDED
BY OUTLAWS,
BUT MY PARENTS
FOUGHT BACK AGAINST THEM.
I WAS SO SCARED, BUT THEY
TOLD ME NOT TO WORRY.
THEY WOULD PROTECT ME.
AND THEY DID.
MY PARENTS SAVED ME
AND THE ENTIRE VILLAGE.
BUT THEY DIED IN THE FIGHT.
MOM AND POP MEANT
EVERYTHING TO ME.
THEY WERE MY WHOLE LIFE.
- [sniffles]
- EVER SINCE THEN,
I'VE BEEN ON MY OWN
AND ON THE RUN.
THOSE SAME OUTLAWS
ARE STILL AFTER ME.
- WELL, YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE
ON THE RUN ANYMORE.
RIGHT, GUYS?
TELL HIM.
- I'M SO SORRY
ABOUT YOUR PARENTS.
I KNOW WE COULD NEVER
REPLACE THEM,
BUT WE'RE HERE FOR YOU.
- WE'LL KEEP YOU SAFE.
COME ON.
- WHEN YOU BOARD
THIS AIRSHIP,
YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE
YOUR OLD LIFE BEHIND
AND START A NEW PATH.
THAT'S
SOME BIG BROTHER ADVICE.
JUST THINK OF ME
AS YOUR BIG BROTHER.
- GUYS, I THINK WE GOT TROUBLE.
[wheels screech]
- RELEASE THE BOY
OR WE'LL TAKE HIM BY FORCE.
- THE OUTLAWS--
THEY'RE AFTER ME.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
- WE'RE NOT RUNNING FROM ANYONE.
IF YOU WANT KAI,
YOU'LL HAVE TO GO THROUGH ME!
[men groan]
- [grunts]
[rock shatters]
[groans]
- YOUR DAYS OF HARASSING
AN INNOCENT BOY ARE OVER.
YOU OUTLAWS ARE GOING TO PRISON.
- OUTLAWS?
INNOCENT BOY?
I'M A SHERIFF
AND THESE ARE MY DEPUTIES.
AND THIS KID IS A THIEF.
WHATEVER HE TOLD YOU IS A LIE.
WE'VE BEEN CHASING HIM
FOR MONTHS.
- WHERE'S KAI?
- RIGHT HERE.
I FOUND HIM SLIPPING AWAY.
- I WAS GOING TO THE BATHROOM.
- WITH YOUR SACK OF GOLD?
- I TOLD YOU,
I FOUND THAT ON THE ROAD!
- ENOUGH WITH THE LIES, KID.
I WANT THE TRUTH.
- THE TRUTH IS, HE'S THE OUTLAW.
HE SPENT HIS ENTIRE LIFE
AS AN ORPHAN
UNTIL HE GOT ADOPTED BY
A REAL NICE FAMILY
ABOUT SIX MONTHS AGO.
AND HOW DID HE REPAY THEM?
BY TAKING THEIR ENTIRE
LIFE SAVINGS.
WE'VE BEEN AFTER HIM
EVER SINCE.
- IS THAT TRUE?
- THE PERSON WHO STOLE
THAT STUFF WAS THE OLD ME.
ONCE I GOT AIRBENDING,
I CHANGED.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO EXPLAIN IT,
BUT I FEEL LIKE AIRBENDING
CHOSE ME FOR A REASON.
LIKE I'M A NEW PERSON.
I'M SORRY! PLEASE!
YOU HAVE TO LISTEN TO ME.
- ARE YOU TAKING HIM BACK
TO THE ORPHANAGE?
- NO. HE'S HEADED TO JAIL.
- WAIT!
YOU GUYS GOT
THE FAMILY'S LIFE SAVINGS BACK.
NOW LET US TAKE KAI.
- DO YOU REALLY WANT
OUR FIRST NEW MEMBER
OF THE AIR NATION
TO BE A LIAR AND A THIEF?
- HE JUST NEEDS SOME GUIDANCE,
TENZIN.
AND WHO BETTER TO GIVE IT
TO HIM THAN US?
- DO YOU WANT THIS KID OR NOT?
- YES. YOU CAN RELEASE
THE BOY INTO OUR CUSTODY.
- THANK YOU.
- DON'T MAKE ME REGRET IT.
- WELCOME TO THE FAMILY,
LITTLE BRO.
- I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW,
I'M GOING TO BE
WATCHING YOU, KID.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT
YOU'RE ALL ABOUT
BECAUSE I'VE BEEN THERE BEFORE.
YOU DON'T HAVE ME FOOLED.
- WHOA, HEY, LIGHTEN UP.
I'M TURNING OVER A NEW LEAF.
MAKING A CHANGE.
DON'T YOU WORRY ABOUT ME.
- HI, I'M JINORA.
IF YOU NEED ANY HELP
WITH AIRBENDING
I COULD SHOW YOU WHAT I KNOW.
- THANKS.
THAT'S REAL NICE OF YOU.
- JINORA!
WE'RE LEAVING NOW.
- THEY CAME OUT OF NOWHERE.
I'M SO SORRY, LORD ZUKO.
- HOW COULD YOU LET THIS HAPPEN?
- THEY CAUGHT US BY SURPRISE.
AND ZAHEER IS
AN AIRBENDER NOW.
- NO!
THIS CAN'T BE.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA THE POWER
THESE CRIMINALS POSSESS?
INDIVIDUALLY, THEY CAN TAKE
DOWN ANY BENDER.
PUT THEM ALL TOGETHER,
THEY COULD TAKE DOWN
THE ENTIRE WORLD.
AND NOW YOU'RE TELLING ME
THEIR LEADER IS AN AIRBENDER?
- WE CAN TRACK THEM...
- WE DON'T NEED TO TRACK THEM.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHERE
THEY'RE GOING.
NOTIFY THE NEW CHIEFS OF
THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE
THAT AN ATTACK ON THEIR PRISON
IS IMMINENT.
AND SEND WORD TO LIN BEIFONG
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
THE AVATAR MUST BE PROTECTED.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- TO STOP THEM.