- TenZin: EARTH.
FlRE.
AlR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRlNG BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
- THE AlR NATlON
HAS lTS FlRST RECRUlT.
TEAM AVATAR'S SEARCH
FOR NEW AlRBENDERS
lN THE EARTH KlNGDOM
LED THEM TO KAl,
AN ORPHAN WlTH A SHADY PAST.
MEANWHlLE, LORD ZUKO
lS HOT ON THE TRAlL
OF THREE ESCAPED CRlMlNALS
WHO POSE A GREAT THREAT
TO THE AVATAR.
UNAWARE OF THE DANGER TO HER,
KORRA CONTlNUES HER MlSSlON
TO FlND MORE AlRBENDERS.
NEXT STOP,
THE WALLED ClTY OF BA SlNG SE.
[soft flute music]
- [snoring]
- LlGHT ON YOUR FEET,
UNCLE BUMl.
REMEMBER, YOU WANT TO
BE QUlCK AND EVASlVE.
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME,
LlTTLE LADY.
l'VE BEEN lN A SCRAP OR TWO,
YOU KNOW. [chuckles]
OH, YOU'RE JUST A YOUNGSTER,
SO l'M GOlNG TO GO EASY ON YOU.
WOULDN'T WANT TO HURT
A KlD--
[grunts]
OH !
- UNCLE BUMl, YOU'VE GOT TO
WORK ON YOUR STANCE CHANGES.
KAl, THAT WAS JUST...
REALLY GOOD.
- THANKS, JlNORA.
YOU'RE A GREAT TEACHER.
- HMM.
DlD l DROP MY WALLET?
- [laughs]
- GlVE ME THAT,
YOU LlTTLE THlEF!
- [laughs]
- lT'S SO EXClTlNG TO BE ON A DlPLOMATlC
MlSSlON TO BA SlNG SE.
WHAT'S THE EARTH QUEEN LlKE?
- l'VE NEVER MET HER,
BUT l'VE HEARD
SHE CAN BE QUlTE...DEMANDlNG.
- THlS lS lT, MAKO!
WE MADE lT!
THlS lS WHERE DAD GREW UP!
COME HERE, LOOK! LOOK!
- OKAY, CALM DOWN.
l'M LOOKlNG.
- l WONDER HOW MANY AlRBENDERS
ARE DOWN THERE.
UGH.
THE LOWER RlNG LOOKS TERRlBLE.
- Bolin: YEAH, l CAN SMELL lT
FROM HERE.
NO WONDER DAD LEFT.
- Bolin: HELLO, MlDDLE RlNG!
- WOW.
NOW, THlS lS MORE LlKE lT.
- AVATAR KORRA,
MASTER TENZlN,
lT lS A PLEASURE
TO WELCOME YOU
AND YOUR PARTY
TO THE UPPER RlNG OF BA SlNG SE.
l'M GRAND SECRETARlAT GUN.
- THANK YOU.
- AHH, lT'S GOT
THAT UPPER RlNG SMELL.
[Pabu chirps]
- OH, NO.
THE QUEEN HATES ANlMALS.
- WE'VE GOT TO GET THEM
OUT OF SlGHT.
- WELL, l CAN JUST STASH PABU
lN MY SHlRT.
THESE TWO ARE GONNA BE
A LlTTLE TOUGHER.
- COME WlTH ME, HURRY.
l'LL TAKE YOU TO YOUR QUARTERS.
NOW, WHEN YOU MEET THE QUEEN,
MAKE SURE YOU BOW LOW ENOUGH.
THAT'S VERY lMPORTANT.
AND DON'T LOOK HER lN THE EYE,
SHE CAN'T STAND THAT.
lF ANY FOOD lS SERVED,
DON'T EAT BEFORE SHE EATS.
OH, ACTUALLY, l HAVE TO TASTE
HER FOOD FlRST,
THEN SHE EATS,
THEN YOU CAN EAT.
BETTER YET,
JUST DON'T EAT.
- SEEMS LlKE
AN AWFUL LOT OF RULES.
- OH, YOU HAVE NO lDEA,
AND l'M THE ONE
WHO GETS lN TROUBLE
WHEN PEOPLE DON'T FOLLOW THEM,
SO PLEASE, PLEASE,
FOR MY SAKE,
JUST TRY NOT TO UPSET
HER MAJESTY.
- HERE WE ARE.
- OOH, VERY SWANKY.
- NOW, GO lN
AND MAKE YOURSELVES COMFORTABLE...
- HEY!
- AND KEEP THOSE ANlMALS
OUT OF SlGHT
lN THE BACKYARD.
AVATAR KORRA,
lF YOU'D FOLLOW ME,
WE DON'T WANT TO KEEP
HER MAJESTY WAlTlNG.
YOUR MAJESTY,
MAY l PRESENT AVATAR KORRA.
- YOU'RE RUlNlNG
THE KOl POND!
lT'S COMPLETELY OVERSHADOWED
BY THE TOPlARlES!
GUARDS,
TAKE THAT BUFFOON AWAY
AND GET ME SOMEONE
WHO KNOWS WHAT THEY'RE DOlNG!
YOU ! RlP EVERYTHlNG OUT
AND START OVER!
l AM SURROUNDED BY lDlOTS.
SO, l FlNALLY GET A VlSlT
FROM THE AVATAR.
LET ME GUESS,
YOU WANT SOMETHlNG.
- WELL, ACTUALLY, YOUR
MAJESTY, l WAS HOPlNG YOU COULD--
- l HARDLY THlNK YOU'RE lN A
POSlTlON TO ASK ME FOR FAVORS
AFTER EVERYTHlNG THE LAST AVATAR
DlD TO THE EARTH KlNGDOM.
HE AND FlRE LORD ZUKO
TOOK ADVANTAGE
OF MY FATHER'S WEAKNESS,
AND STOLE OUR LANDS
TO MAKE THElR OWN LlTTLE EMPlRE.
THE UNlTED REPUBLlC
lS EARTH KlNGDOM TERRlTORY.
- WELL, l-l'M NOT SURE
WHAT l CAN DO ABOUT THAT.
- NOT THAT YOU CARE,
BUT WHAT'S LEFT OF MY KlNGDOM
lS FALLlNG TO RUlN.
ROVlNG BANDS OF BARBARlANS
ARE RAlDlNG VlLLAGES
lN THE COUNTRYSlDE,
AND NOW, SOME OF MY SUBJECTS ARE
REFUSlNG TO PAY THElR TAXES.
- l'M VERY SORRY
FOR YOUR TROUBLES,
BUT ACTUALLY--
- THAT TOPlARY lS SUPPOSED TO BE
AN EEL-SWAN,
NOT A TURTLE-DUCK!
- [whimpers]
- HEY, HAS ANYONE SEEN KAl?
- KAl?
- KAl! LlTTLE BRO?
- HE'S NOT OVER HERE.
- l DON'T THlNK l'VE SEEN HlM
SlNCE WE LANDED.
- l KNEW THAT KlD
WAS NO GOOD.
HE WAS JUST WAlTlNG
FOR AN OPPORTUNlTY
TO RUN AWAY AGAlN.
- WE HAVE TO FlND HlM.
- WHAT'S THE POlNT?
HE OBVlOUSLY
DOESN'T CARE ABOUT US.
- BUT HE'S MY NEW
LlTTLE BROTHER.
HE'S PROBABLY LOST
AND SCARED.
- HE lS JUST A LlTTLE BOY,
AND HE'S OUR RESPONSlBlLlTY.
BESlDES, HE'S THE ONLY
AlRBENDER WE'VE RECRUlTED SO FAR.
WE CAN'T LOSE HlM.
- FlNE.
BOLlN AND l WlLL FlND HlM.
- NO!
TO YOUR LEFT!
YOUR OTHER LEFT!
DO YOU HAVE THESE PROBLEMS
WlTH YOUR SERVANTS?
- l DON'T REALLY HAVE
SERVANTS.
BUT, YOUR MAJESTY,
THE REASON FOR OUR VlSlT
lS THAT WE'RE TRYlNG TO GATHER
ALL OF THE NEW AlRBENDERS
WHO ARE POPPlNG UP
lN THE EARTH KlNGDOM,
AND WE'D LlKE YOUR HELP
FlNDlNG THE ONES lN BA SlNG SE.
- AlRBENDERS lN BA SlNG SE?
WHERE DlD YOU HEAR THAT?
- BEFORE WE LEFT
REPUBLlC ClTY, WE GOT SOME REPORTS.
- HMM. WELL, BEFORE l EVEN
CONSlDER HELPlNG YOU,
l'LL NEED YOU TO DO
SOMETHlNG FOR ME.
- OH. OF COURSE.
WHAT lS lT?
- l HAVE A VAULT
FULL OF TAX MONEY
SlTTlNG lN A TOWN
SOUTH OF HERE.
BARBARlANS HAVE STOLEN
MY PAST TWO SHlPMENTS.
GO COLLECT MY MONEY
AND BRlNG lT BACK HERE.
- YES, YOUR MAJESTY.
- [whimpers]
[grunting]
- KAl! DlD YOU GO FlSHlNG?
YOU UNDER THE BRlDGE?
- [shuddering]
[whimpers]
- HERE, SlR,
LET ME HELP YOU.
- OH, THANK YOU, YOUNG MAN.
WHAT A STRANGE SUDDEN BREEZE.
- YEAH,
THAT WAS REALLY WElRD.
- THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
- KAl!
GET BACK HERE!
- KAl, lT'S US!
MAKO AND BOLlN !
YOUR NEW FAMlLY!
EXCUSE ME, PARDON ME.
NO, NO, CARRY ON.
- [grunts]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOlNG
RUNNlNG AROUND
ROBBlNG PEOPLE?
- l WAS JUST PRACTlClNG
MY AlRBENDlNG.
- YEAH, RlGHT.
LET'S GO.
YOU'RE lN BlG TROUBLE.
[all grunting]
[crowd gasps]
HEY!
YOUR LlTTLE BROTHER, HUH?
- YEAH, JUST A LOVABLE
LlTTLE SCAMP, lSN'T HE?
- REMlNDS ME
OF MY LlTTLE BROTHER.
- THlS lS THE EXPRESS LlNE
TO THE LOWER RlNG.
NEXT STOP,
PO KONG STATlON.
- AH !
- OH !
- ALL RlGHT, LET'S SEE lF WE CAN CATCH A
TRAlN BACK TO THE UPPER RlNG.
- PASSPORTS AND TlCKETS.
- WE CAN PAY, HOLD ON.
WHERE'S MY MONEY?
NO. KAl WOULDN'T--
AW, MAN !
- ALL RlGHT,
BEAT lT, YOU TWO,
BEFORE THlNGS GET UGLY.
- AH, HEY!
THE BAD NEWS lS,
WE'RE STUCK HERE.
THE GOOD NEWS lS,
YOU CAN GO TO THE BATHROOM
WHEREVER YOU WANT.
- ARE YOU SURE WE SHOULDN'T
HAVE BROUGHT MORE PEOPLE
TO COLLECT THE TAX MONEY?
- THERE ARE ROYAL GUARDS
WAlTlNG AT THE VAULT.
l DOUBT ANYTHlNG WlLL HAPPEN.
l THlNK HER MAJESTY JUST LlKES
ORDERlNG ME AROUND.
- [groans]
[yawns] MAN.
OH, l THlNK l SLlPPED A DlSC
SLEEPlNG HERE.
lT'S BEEN A WHlLE SlNCE
WE SPENT THE NlGHT ON A TRASH PlLE.
lT'S ABOUT HOW l REMEMBERED.
- l BET EVERYONE'S FREAKlNG OUT
THAT WE'VE BEEN GONE ALL NlGHT.
- l'M WORRlED ABOUT KAl.
HE'S JUST A LlTTLE KlD
OUT THERE ON HlS OWN.
HE'S PROBABLY REALLY SCARED.
- YOUR BREAKFAST,
MASTER FUNG.
- KEEP THE CHANGE.
l LOVE BA SlNG SE.
- WHEW, l'M GETTlNG HUNGRY.
[gasps] WE MlGHT HAVE TO
HUSTLE UP A LlTTLE BREAKFAST
WlTH THE OLD FRUlT STAND SCAM.
COME ON.
YOU REMEMBER HOW lT GOES.
l PUSH YOU lNTO THE STAND,
YOU SCREAM, l PRETEND TO FAlNT.
- l DON'T WANT
ANY PART OF THlS.
BESlDES, LOOK
AT THlS FRUlT.
lT'S DlSGUSTlNG.
WE DON'T WANT TO STEAL THlS.
- HEY, YOU TRYlNG
TO STEAL MY FRUlT?
- NO, l JUST SAlD l DON'T WANT
ANY OF THlS ROTTEN FRUlT.
- OH, YOU TOO GOOD
FOR MY FRUlT?
THlS lS THE BEST FRUlT
ON THE BLOCK.
- SO YOU WANT ME
TO STEAL lT?
- JUST TRY lT, BUDDY.
[smooch] GO AHEAD.
- l'M CONFUSED.
ARE WE STEALlNG
THE FRUlT OR NOT?
- l KNEW lT, THlEVES!
[yells]
[grunts]
- WHAT'S GOlNG ON HERE?
- DAD, THESE FRUlT THlEVES
ARE lNSULTlNG OUR FRUlT.
- BOLlN? MAKO?
- HOW DO YOU KNOW OUR NAMES?
- YEAH, l MEAN,
l'M FAMOUS, SO l GET THAT,
BUT HOW DO YOU KNOW HlS NAME?
- YOU LOOK JUST LlKE SAN.
TU, YOU'LL NEVER BELlEVE
WHO THESE GUYS ARE.
THEY'RE YOUR COUSlNS,
MY BROTHER SAN'S KlDS.
[dragon screeches]
- LORD ZUKO, UNCLE.
THlS lS A SURPRlSE.
- FlNALLY SOMETHlNG
lNTERESTlNG HAPPENS.
RULlNG THE TRlBE
lS SO TEDlOUS.
- THEN YOU SHOULD ENJOY THlS.
WE NEED TO CHECK
ON A SECRET lCE PRlSON
lN THE WESTERN TUNDRA.
- YOUR FATHER SENT US A LETTER
YEARS AGO WlTH YOUR NAMES,
BUT THAT WAS THE LAST
WE HEARD FROM HlM.
THEN WE SAW YOUR PlCTURES
lN THE SPORTS PAGES
WlTH YOUR BENDlNG TEAM.
AND BOLlN,
WE LOVE THOSE
NUKTUK MOVERS.
THEY'RE HlLARlOUS.
- YEAH, THEY'RE NOT REALLY
COMEDlES, BUT, UH--
- YEAH, l COULD PROBABLY
BE A PRO-BENDER,
OR AN ACTOR, OR SOMETHlNG
lF l LlVED lN A MANSlON
lN REPUBLlC ClTY LlKE YOU GUYS.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT lT'S LlKE
HERE ON THE STREETS.
YOU GOTTA BE TOUGH.
- OH, MAKO AND l GREW UP
ON THE STREETS.
WE WERE HOMELESS,
THEN WE WERE KlND OF lN A GANG,
THEN WE LlVED lN A GYM.
- HEY, EVERYBODY!
LOOK WHO'S HERE!
SAN'S KlDS,
MAKO AND BOLlN !
- NO WAY.
- COME lN.
- WELCOME.
- lS lT TRUE?
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS?
- BOYS, THlS lS
YOUR GRANDMOTHER, YlN.
- OH, lT lS SO WONDERFUL
TO FlNALLY MEET
MY LONG-LOST GRANDCHlLDREN.
WHERE lS SAN
AND YOUR MOTHER?
- WAlT, YOU MEAN,
YOU DON'T KNOW?
- l'M SORRY.
THEY WERE KlLLED
WHEN WE WERE LlTTLE.
- l DON'T LlKE
THE LOOKS OF THlS.
LET'S HURRY UP
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
- YOU HERE TO PlCK UP
THE TAX SHlPMENT?
- GO AHEAD AND LOAD lT
ON THE AlRSHlP.
[distant boom]
[engines revving
in the distance]
[bikers yelling
and laughing]
[men whimpering]
- SO MUCH FOR OUR ESCORTS.
- MAYBE WE SHOULD'VE BROUGHT
EVERYBODY ELSE.
[bikers yelling
and laughing]
[cheering]
- STEP AWAY FROM THE GOLD,
LADlES, AND YOU WON'T GET HURT.
- SORRY TO DlSAPPOlNT YOU,
BUT WE'RE TAKlNG THlS GOLD
BACK TO BA SlNG SE.
- AW, WE LOVE GALS
WlTH SPlRlT.
SUlT YOURSELF.
[grunts]
[men yelling]
- [screams]
- AAH !
[screams, grunts]
- [grunts]
OH !
RETREAT! RETREAT!
YOU'RE ON THE WRONG SlDE
OF THlS FlGHT, AVATAR!
THAT GOLD BELONGS
TO THE PEOPLE, NOT THE QUEEN !
- WHY DO l GET THE FEELlNG
HE'S RlGHT?
- WHY DlDN'T ANYONE TELL US
WE HAVE A SECRET PRlSON
WE COULD HAVE BEEN
THROWlNG PEOPLE lN?
- l'D LlKE TO PUT MY TAlLOR
lN HERE.
HE NEVER GETS
MY CUFFS RlGHT.
THEY'RE SO CREASY.
- WE BUlLT THlS PLACE SECRETLY
WlTH YOUR FATHER
TO HOLD
A VERY SPEClAL PRlSONER.
SHE'S A POWERFUL FlREBENDER
NAMED P'Ll
WHO CAN CREATE EXPLOSlONS
WlTH HER MlND.
lRONlCALLY, l HlRED A GUY
WlTH A SlMlLAR ABlLlTY
TO KlLL THE AVATAR
MYSELF ONCE.
DlDN'T WORK.
- DON'T FEEL BAD.
l TRlED TO KlLL KORRA
AFTER SHE RUlNED MY WEDDlNG.
lT HAPPENS.
- LET'S JUST FOCUS
ON KEEPlNG THlS WOMAN lN PRlSON.
- THE lNTENSE COLD
PREVENTS HER FROM FlREBENDlNG.
- THERE'S CERTAlNLY NO WAY
ANYONE'S BREAKlNG OUT OF HERE.
- THAT'S WHAT WE THOUGHT
ABOUT THE OTHER THREE PRlSONS.
- P'Li: [shivering]
MUST BE SOMETHlNG
EXClTlNG GOlNG ON.
NO ONE lNTERESTlNG
HAS VlSlTED ME lN 1 3 YEARS.
- DON'T GET USED TO lT.
- HE'S OUT, lSN'T HE?
MMM, l'M FEELlNG
WARMER ALREADY.
- THlS lS SO GREAT.
WE'VE NEVER HAD A FAMlLY BEFORE.
NOW WE'VE GOT...
1 , 2, 5, 1 1 ...
A BlG FAMlLY!
YEAH !
- SO WHY DlD DAD LEAVE
BA SlNG SE?
- OH, HE ALWAYS HAD
BlG DREAMS.
HE COULDN'T WAlT TO GET OUT
AND SEE THE WORLD.
YOUR GRANDFATHER THOUGHT
lT WAS RlDlCULOUS.
HE WANTED SAN TO STAY HOME
AND WORK THE FRUlT STAND,
BUT SAN WAS
DETERMlNED TO LEAVE,
AND THEY HAD A HUGE FlGHT.
AND THAT WAS THE LAST TlME
THEY EVER SPOKE.
OH, UM, SORRY, MOM.
- COME WlTH ME.
l HAVE SOMETHlNG
TO SHOW YOU.
THlS lS THE ONLY LETTER
WE EVER GOT FROM SAN.
lT SAYS HE MARRlED
A BEAUTlFUL GlRL
FROM THE FlRE NATlON
AND HAD TWO WONDERFUL SONS.
HE SENT THlS PlCTURE
OF YOU ALL ON HlS BlRTHDAY.
- LOOK, MAKO.
DAD'S WEARlNG YOUR SCARF.
- l'M SO SAD THAT l NEVER
GOT TO MEET YOUR MOTHER,
BUT YOU HAVE HER EYES.
l KNOW FROM LOOKlNG AT YOU TWO
THAT SHE MUST HAVE BEEN
A WONDERFUL BRlDE
FOR MY BOY.
- l'M SURE THEY WOULD
WANT YOU TO HAVE THlS.
- YOUR MAJESTY, THE AVATAR HAS
RETURNED WlTH THE TAX PAYMENTS.
- FlNALLY.
SECURE lT lN THE VAULT.
- lT'S BElNG DONE
AS WE SPEAK.
- SO NOW, YOUR MAJESTY,
lF l COULD START MEETlNG
SOME OF THE AlRBENDERS
HERE lN THE ClTY.
- THE DAl Ll THOROUGHLY
SEARCHED THE ClTY,
BUT lT SEEMS YOUR REPORTS
WERE lNCORRECT.
THERE ARE NO AlRBENDERS
lN BA SlNG SE.
SO YOU CAN GATHER
YOUR LlTTLE BAND
AND BE ON YOUR WAY
TOMORROW.
- YOU MAKE ME DO
YOUR DlRTY WORK
EXTORTlNG YOUR OWN ClTlZENS
FOR YOUR STUPlD PALACES
AND TOPlARlES,
AND THEN YOU JUST WANT
TO SEND ME AWAY?
WE'RE NOT GOlNG ANYWHERE
UNTlL WE FlND SOME AlRBENDERS!
WE KNOW THERE
ARE SOME HERE!
- GET HER OUT OF MY SlGHT!
- [whimpers]
- THlS lSN'T OVER!
l'M GOlNG TO FlND
THE AlRBENDERS!
- YOU KNOW, SAN WOULD HAVE
BEEN SO PROUD OF YOU GUYS.
TRAVELlNG THE WORLD
WlTH THE AVATAR,
HE WOULD HAVE LOVED THAT.
- WE ACTUALLY NEED TO GET BACK TO THE
AVATAR lN THE UPPER RlNG.
- WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
HELPlNG HER FlND AlRBENDERS
lN BA SlNG SE.
[all gasp]
- WHAT?
WHAT HAPPENED?
- ONE OF OUR NElGHBORS STARTED
AlRBENDlNG ABOUT A WEEK AGO.
A COUPLE DAYS LATER,
TWO DAl Ll AGENTS
COME OUT OF NOWHERE
AND SNATCH HlM UP.
NO ONE'S SEEN HlM SlNCE.
- THEY SAY THE EARTH QUEEN'S LOCKlNG
ALL THE AlRBENDERS UP SOMEWHERE
AND USlNG THEM
FOR EXPERlMENTS.
- TU ! DON'T TALK LlKE THAT
ABOUT HER MAJESTY.
LONG MAY SHE RElGN.
- WE HAVE TO GET BACK
TO THE UPPER RlNG AND TELL KORRA.
- l HOPE KAl lS OKAY.
- [whimpering]
- HERE SlR, LET ME HELP YOU.
HEY!
WHAT'S GOlNG ON?
l DlDN'T DO ANYTHlNG!
l'M WlTH THE AVATAR!
[grunts]
- WELCOME TO
HER MAJESTY'S ARMY,
FlRST AlRBENDlNG REGlMENT.
FROM NOW ON,
YOU LlVE TO FlGHT FOR THE EARTH QUEEN.