- Tenzin: EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
AIRBENDERS ARE
MYSTERIOUSLY DISAPPEARING
IN BA SING SE,
INCLUDING KAI.
THE EARTH QUEEN DENIED ANY
KNOWLEDGE OF THE AIRBENDERS,
BUT KORRA REFUSED
TO GIVE UP HER SEARCH.
MEANWHILE, MAKO AND BOLIN
MET THEIR LONG-LOST RELATIVES,
WHO TOLD THEM
THAT DAI LI AGENTS
HAVE BEEN ROUNDING UP
AIRBENDERS FOR THE QUEEN'S ARMY.
AND AT A PRISON
IN THE NORTH,
TONRAQ AND LORD ZUKO PREPARE
FOR ZAHEER'S IMMINENT ATTACK.
- DID YOU SEE ZAHEER?
THE ONLY THING I SAW
WAS A SNOWSTORM HEADING OUR WAY.
THAT'S NOT A SNOWSTORM.
THAT'S HIM.
I PUT YOU AWAY ONCE, ZAHEER,
AND I'M GOING TO DO IT AGAIN.
- MING-HUA.
- LET'S GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
WE COULD HAVE JUST TAKEN
THE ELEVATOR, SHOW-OFF.
I'VE WAITED 13 YEARS
TO FEEL THIS WARM.
I THOUGHT
I'D NEVER SEE YOU AGAIN.
- I NEVER DOUBTED.
- REALLY? RIGHT NOW?
- I GOT 'EM!
THESE PASSPORTS SHOULD GET YOU
INTO THE UPPER RING.
AWESOME! TU, YOU'RE THE BEST
COUSIN A GUY COULD HAVE.
AND MY OTHER COUSINS
AS WELL.
YEAH.
YEAH, YOU'RE ALL THE BEST.
THANKS.
I KNOW THIS WASN'T EASY.
IT'S SUCH A SHAME
YOU TWO MUST LEAVE SO SOON.
- I WISH WE COULD STAY.
BUT IF IT'S TRUE
THE EARTH QUEEN
IS FORCING AIRBENDERS
INTO HER ARMY,
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT IT.
I LOVE YOU BOTH.
COME VISIT AGAIN.
- WE WILL, GRANDMA.
- I LOVE YOU TOO, GRANDMA.
AND CHOW AND TU
AND MENG-MENG
AND CHOW JR.
AND THERE HE IS,
BIG TEE AND LITTLE... LITTLE TEE,
AND MEDIUM YU AND...AND...
AND WHAT WAS YOUR NAME AGAIN?
I KNOW THAT EARTH QUEEN
IS LYING TO ME.
I CAN TELL BY THAT STUPID
LITTLE QUEENY SMIRK OF HERS!
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE
I HELPED HER.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
SHE WAS USING ME!
- WHOA! HEY!
I THINK I COULD USE A BREAK.
YOU LETTING OFF STEAM
IS STARTING TO...
HURT...A LOT.
- SORRY.
MAKO! BOLIN!
YOU'RE OKAY.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
- WE CHASED KAI...
TRAIN...
SLIPPED AWAY...
LOWER RING...
SLEPT IN TRASH PILE...
MET OUR FAMILY...
GRANDMA, TEARS...
MAKO SCARF...
EARTH QUEEN LYING.
MM.
- CAN YOU INTERPRET THAT?
THE EARTH QUEEN'S BEEN
SECRETLY TAKING AIRBENDERS
AND FORCING THEM
INTO HER ARMY.
SHE WAS LYING.
I KNEW IT!
I SWEAR,
THE NEXT TIME I SEE HER...
- IT'S THE QUEEN.
QUICK, PABU, SHIRT!
I KNOW. SORRY.
KINDA SWEATY.
GOOD, YOU'RE HERE.
GUN, TELL HER THE NEWS.
WE'VE RECEIVED WORD
FROM THE YANG PROVINCE.
THERE HAVE BEEN REPORTS
OF AIRBENDERS THERE.
- WONDERFUL, ISN'T IT?
IT'S THE VERY THING
YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR.
- THANK YOU.
THAT IS JUST
THE MOST WONDERFUL NEWS, EVER.
YAY.
SO I ASSUME YOU AND YOUR...
FRIENDS HERE
WILL BE LEAVING IMMEDIATELY.
AHHH, AH-CHOO!
AH-CHOO!
AHHHH, AH-CHOO!
IS THERE AN ANIMAL
IN MY PRESENCE?
- NO, YOUR MAJESTY.
I WOULD NEVER ALLOW
AN ANIMAL NEAR YOU.
AH-CHOO!
AHH, AHH, AH-CHOO!
IF I FIND ONE WITHIN
50 FEET OF ME,
IT'S YOUR HEAD!
ANYWAY, IF YOU NEED
ANY ASSISTANCE PACKING,
LET GUN KNOW.
HE'LL SEE TO IT THAT YOU ARE
ON YOUR WAY BY EVENING.
- Kcrra: UH, THIS EVENING?
I'M NOT SURE
ABOUT LEAVING SO SOON.
BECAUSE OUR AIRSHIP
IS HAVING ENGINE TROUBLE.
IT'LL TAKE ME UNTIL TOMORROW
TO FINISH THE REPAIRS.
AHH, AHH, AH-CHOO!
AH-CHOO!
THANKS FOR BUYING US
SOME TIME.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THE EARTH QUEEN
IS CONSCRIPTING AIRBENDERS.
THOSE PEOPLE SHOULD NOT
BE FORCED TO JOIN AN ARMY.
- WELL, TECHNICALLY,
THE EARTH QUEEN HAS A RIGHT
TO CONSCRIPT HER CITIZENS.
WHAT?
IT'S TRUE.
GUYS, WHAT IF KAI
WAS SPOTTED AIRBENDING?
HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
TAKEN TOO.
- PROBABLY NOT.
HE'S SURPRISINGLY DIFFICULT
TO CATCH.
LIKE A...LIKE A LITTLE
GREASED HOG-MONKEY.
- BUT WHAT IF HE WAS?
DON'T WORRY, JINORA.
WE'LL FIND HIM.
WE JUST NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE TO LOOK.
I BET
THEY'RE UNDER LAKE LAOGAI.
WHAT? I'VE BEEN READING
SOME OF JINORA'S BOOKS.
THE OLD DAI LI AGENTS
USED TO HAVE A SECRET FORTRESS
BENEATH THE LAKE.
- MAKO'S RIGHT.
IT'S THE PERFECT SPOT
TO HIDE AIRBENDERS.
AND I KNOW HOW TO CHECK IT OUT
WITHOUT BEING CAUGHT.
I CAN PROJECT MY SPIRIT
INTO IT.
YOU MEAN
THAT OUT-OF-BODY THING YOU DID
TO HELP GIANT SPIRITY-KORRA?
- YOU CAN STILL DO THAT?
IT'S NOT AS POWERFUL AS IT WAS
DURING HARMONIC CONVERGENCE,
BUT IF I CAN GET CLOSE ENOUGH,
I THINK I CAN DO IT.
- LET'S GO GET KAI OUT.
LET'S GET
ALL THE AIRBENDERS OUT.
YOU ARE THE PROPERTY
OF THE EARTH KINGDOM.
YOU WILL BECOME THE EARTH
QUEEN'S ELITE FIGHTING FORCE
AND PROTECT HER AT ALL COST.
IT IS YOUR DUTY
TO SERVE THE EARTH QUEEN.
- AAH!
- GO EASY ON ME.
I'M NOT THAT GOOD.
- NEVER SHOW MERCY!
NOW ATTACK YOUR OPPONENT,
AND THIS TIME,
LIKE YOU MEAN IT.
- SORRY.
A SOLDIER NEVER APOLOGIZES
TO HIS ENEMY.
- I'M NOT A SOLDIER.
YOU WILL BE
WHEN I'M THROUGH WITH YOU.
IF ANYTHING GOES WRONG,
COME BACK IMMEDIATELY.
- I WILL.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
THE AIRBENDERS AREN'T THERE.
IT'S COMPLETELY DESERTED.
- THEY'RE NOT DOWN THERE?
JINORA, YOU'VE READ
ALL ABOUT BA SING SE.
CAN YOU THINK
OF ANY OTHER PLACES
THE AIRBENDERS MIGHT BE?
I GUESS THEY COULD BE
IN THE CATACOMBS
BENEATH THE UPPER RING
OR THE ANCIENT SEWERS
BENEATH THE LOWER RING
OR THE MAZE OF TUNNELS THAT
CONNECTS THE RINGS TOGETHER,
OR THEY COULD BE...
THERE ARE
JUST TOO MANY PLACES.
THERE HAS TO BE
ANOTHER WAY TO LOCATE THEM.
- MAYBE THERE IS.
HOW DID YOU FIND ME
DURING HARMONIC CONVERGENCE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST KIND OF FOCUSED
ON YOUR ENERGY.
I THINK OUR
SPIRITUAL CONNECTION LED ME TO YOU.
MAYBE YOU CAN FIND KAI
THE SAME WAY.
I KNOW YOU TWO
HAVE A CONNECTION.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
A CONNECTION?
I DON'T KNOW.
LET ME TRY.
- UGH!
THANKS.
- YOU AGAIN!
IF YOU HAVE TIME
TO HELP YOUR FRIEND,
MAYBE YOU'RE NOT GETTING
ENOUGH ROCKS FOR YOURSELF.
I GUESS YOU'RE NOT
AS GOOD AS YOU THOUGHT.
THROW HIM IN THE HOLE!
JINORA?
- IT WORKED!
HOW ARE YOU HERE
RIGHT NOW?
- SHH, QUIET.
IT'S A HIGH-LEVEL
AIRBENDER MOVE...
WITH A LITTLE SPIRITUAL STUFF
THROWN IN.
FOR A SECOND THERE,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A GHOST.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU
AND THE OTHER AIRBENDERS.
WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU ALL
OUT OF HERE.
WHERE ARE WE ANYWAY?
- UNDERGROUND SOMEWHERE.
OTHER THAN THAT,
I DON'T HAVE A CLUE.
I'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
DON'T WORRY.
JINORA...
THANKS.
- THE EARTH QUEEN'S TEMPLE.
Kcrra: I CAN'T BELIEVE
MISS QUEENY SMUGFACE
HAD THEM RIGHT UNDER OUR NOSES
THE WHOLE TIME!
WE HAVE TO GET
INTO THAT COMPOUND TONIGHT
AND GET THOSE
AIRBENDERS OUT.
ALL RIGHT, WE GO IN
UNDER THE COVER OF DARKNESS.
TWO SMALL INSERTION TEAMS
AND A THIRD ON THE OUTSIDE.
THEN ALL WE'LL NEED
IS 12 TONS OF BLASTING JELLY,
A MEDIUM-SIZED BULLDOZER
AND...
DOES ANYONE HAVE A BADGER-MOLE
THAT KNOWS MORSE CODE?
OH, GREAT.
NOT THE QUEEN AGAIN.
EVERYONE ACT NORMAL.
AND, BOLIN...
- I'M ON IT!
WHAT?
HEY, I'M NOT SWEATY
THIS TIME.
AH!
LIN?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WE NEED TO GET KORRA
OUT OF HERE IMMEDIATELY.
HER LIFE'S IN DANGER.
- WHAT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I JUST GOT WORD
FROM LORD ZUKO AND TONRAQ.
WHY IS LORD ZUKO
WITH MY DAD?
ZAHEER AND THE OTHERS
HAVE ESCAPED.
- HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
BECAUSE ZAHEER
IS AN AIRBENDER NOW.
- NO.
- ALL RIGHT, HOLD ON.
WILL YOU QUIT IGNORING ME
AND TELL ME WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHO'S ZAHEER?
WHY IS MY LIFE IN DANGER?
SHORTLY AFTER WE FOUND OUT
YOU WERE THE AVATAR,
ZAHEER AND THREE OTHERS
ATTEMPTED TO KIDNAP YOU.
LUCKILY, YOUR FATHER,
LORD ZUKO, CHIEF SOKKA,
AND I WERE THERE
TO STOP THEM.
WE APPREHENDED THE CRIMINALS AND
LOCKED THEM AWAY IN PRISONS
DESIGNED TO IMPAIR
THEIR ABILITIES.
SO THAT'S WHY YOU AND MY DAD
SHELTERED ME AWAY.
- IT WAS FOR YOUR OWN SAFETY.
WHY WERE THEY TRYING
TO KIDNAP KORRA?
WE SPENT 13 YEARS
INTERROGATING THEM,
BUT THEY NEVER BROKE.
TO THIS DAY, NO ONE KNOWS
WHAT THEIR MOTIVE WAS.
NOW WE NEED TO GET YOU BACK
TO REPUBLIC CITY,
WHERE I CAN PROTECT YOU.
- NO, I'M NOT RUNNING.
KORRA,
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THESE CRIMINALS ARE LIKE
NOTHING YOU'VE EVER FACED BEFORE.
LOOK, I'M NOT
A LITTLE KID ANYMORE.
YOU DON'T NEED
TO PROTECT ME.
I CAME HERE FOR ONE THING...
TO FIND AIRBENDERS...
AND I'M NOT LEAVING
WITHOUT THEM.
FINE, LET'S GET 'EM
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
WHERE ARE THEY?
- IN A MILITARY COMPOUND,
AND WE'RE BUSTING THEM OUT.
- HI.
- HEY! WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
AW, IT'S JUST
THAT LITTLE AIRBENDER GIRL
WHO CAME WITH THE AVATAR.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE WALKING
AROUND HERE ALL ALONE.
- I'M NOT ALONE.
- BUMI AND KORRA,
YOU TWO WILL COME WITH ME
TO FIND THE AIRBENDERS.
YOU THREE FIND KAI.
WE'LL MEET
ON THE SURFACE SHORTLY.
RADIO US
IF ANYTHING GOES WRONG.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHO ARE YOU?
- I'M THE AVATAR,
AND I'M GETTING YOU ALL
OUT OF HERE.
- WE'RE LEAVING?
- WHERE ARE WE GOING?
EVERYONE, PLEASE,
YOU MUST STAY CALM AND QUIET
IF WE WANT THIS TO WORK.
- WHAT TO WORK?
WE'RE SNEAKING OUT?
YES,
AND WE MUST LEAVE NOW.
WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU AWAY FROM
THE EARTH QUEEN AND OUT OF THE CITY.
THERE'S AN AIRBENDER
THAT'S NOT HERE.
HIS NAME IS KAI.
WE NEED TO GET HIM.
WE'RE ALREADY
TAKING CARE OF IT.
TOPSIDE, THIS IS PAPA BEAR.
THE BREEZIES ARE IN THE HOLD.
CUE THE BALLOONS.
WHAT?
ARE YOU IN TROUBLE?
- NO!
WE GOT THE AIRBENDERS,
AND WE'RE HEADED OUT.
BRING THE AIRSHIPS.
NO ONE LIKES CODE NAMES
ANYMORE.
COPY THAT.
ASAMI AND I ARE ON OUR WAY.
COME ON,
WE'RE GETTING YOU OUT.
- KAI!
MWAH!
- WHOA!
TENZIN'S NOT GOING
TO BE HAPPY ABOUT THIS.
- THEN DON'T TELL HIM.
HOW CAN I NOT?
THIS IS TOO JUICY!
THANKS FOR COMING
TO GET ME.
I'M REALLY SORRY
ABOUT STEALING YOUR WALLETS
AND RUNNING AWAY
AND GETTING YOU STUCK
ON THAT TRAIN.
OH, WE CAN'T STAY
MAD AT YOU!
- YES, WE CAN.
I HAD A LOT OF MONEY
IN THAT WALLET!
- GUYS, COME ON.
DESERTING HER MAJESTY'S
ARMY IS HIGH TREASON,
PUNISHABLE BY DEATH.
- COME ON, IT'S CLEAR.
SO YOU'VE DISCOVERED
MY ELITE ARMY.
I SEE THEIR LOYALTY
STILL NEEDS SOME WORK.
THESE AIRBENDERS
SHOULDN'T BE USED AS WEAPONS.
THEY HAVE A RIGHT TO CHOOSE
THEIR OWN PATHS.
THESE AIRBENDERS
ARE EARTH KINGDOM CITIZENS,
AND I AM THEIR QUEEN.
TAKING THEM WILL CONSTITUTE
AN ACT OF WAR.
IF YOU DISOBEY ME,
I WILL BEAR DOWN ON YOU
WITH THE ENTIRE FORCE
OF MY KINGDOM!
- THEY'RE LEAVING WITH ME.
- NO, THEY'RE NOT!
- COME ON!
I GUESS I AM AS GOOD
AS I THOUGHT.
EVERYONE'S IN. LET'S GO!
OOGI!
- TAKE DOWN THOSE AIRSHIPS!
- WHERE ARE THE OTHERS?
- WE NEED HELP!
EVERYBODY, HANG ON!
WHOA, THAT WAS AWESOME!
BRING ME
THOSE AIRSHIPS NOW!
AHH, AH-CHOO!
OH, GET IT OFF ME!
AH-CHOO!
GET THIS FUR OFF...
AHHH-CHOO!
Tenzin: I KNOW THAT NONE OF YOU
CHOSE TO BECOME AIRBENDERS,
BUT NOW YOU DO
HAVE A CHOICE.
WE CAN RELOCATE YOU
SOMEWHERE SAFE,
OR YOU CAN COME WITH ME
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE
TO LIVE IN PEACE
AND TRAIN AS AIR NOMADS.
YOU ARE NO LONGER
ANYONE'S PROPERTY.
WHAT PATH YOU DECIDE
IS UP TO YOU.
- I WANT TO GO WITH YOU.
- ME TOO.
- COUNT ME IN.
- I WANNA GO TOO.
- I'LL GO TOO.
- ME TOO.
- SOUNDS LIKE FUN.
- I WANNA GO TOO.
- OOH, I WANNA GO.
GOOD LUCK
AT THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
I'LL SEND MORE AIRBENDERS
YOUR WAY WHEN I FIND THEM.
BE CAREFUL OUT THERE,
AND STAY SAFE.
- I'LL TRY.
IT SEEMS LIKE WHEREVER I GO,
I MAKE A NEW ENEMY.
BUT YOU MADE
SOME NEW FRIENDS TOO.
YOU DID WELL, KORRA.
THIS IS
ONLY THE BEGINNING.