- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- IS THERE ANY PLACE SAFE
FOR THE AVATAR?
FIRST, PRESIDENT RAIKO
BANISHED HER FROM REPUBLIC CITY.
THEN THE EARTH QUEEN DECLARED
HER AN ENEMY OF THE KINGDOM
AFTER KORRA RESCUED A GROUP
OF AIRBENDERS FROM BA SING SE.
AND NOW KORRA
HAS LEARNED THAT ZAHEER
AND HIS FELLOW CRIMINALS
ARE AFTER HER.
WITH TENZIN BUSY BRINGING
THE NEW RECRUITS
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE,
KORRA'S PROTECTION NOW RESTS
IN BEIFONG'S HANDS.
[Naga growls]
[Naga panting]
- WHILE YOU'RE PLAYING FETCH,
FOUR OF THE MOST DANGEROUS
CRIMINALS IN THE WORLD
ARE HUNTING YOU DOWN.
WE SHOULD GET MOVING.
- RELAX.
WE JUST GOT HERE.
BESIDES, NO ONE KNOWS
WHERE I AM RIGHT NOW EXCEPT US.
I THINK SHE WANTS YOU
TO THROW IT FOR HER.
[Naga whimpering]
- I'LL PASS.
THANKS.
- WE JUST GOT A CALL ON THE
RADIO ABOUT ANOTHER AIRBENDER.
- FINALLY.
WHERE ARE THEY?
- A CITY CALLED ZAOFU,
THE HOME OF THE METAL CLAN.
- YOU KNOW THE PLACE?
- UH, NEVER BEEN, BUT
I DON'T WANT YOU GOING THERE.
I'D REST A LOT EASIER IF YOU
WERE BACK SAFE IN REPUBLIC CITY.
- SORRY, BUT IF THERE'S
AN AIRBENDER IN ZAOFU,
THEN THAT'S WHERE
WE'RE GOING NEXT.
[Naga panting]
[Naga whimpering]
- WOW, WOW, WOW!
AN ENTIRE CITY MADE OF METAL,
WHOO!
YOU SHOULD BE
RIGHT AT HOME, BEIFONG.
- HMM.
[Pabu chirps]
- YEAH!
- AREN'T YOU COMING?
- WHAT'S THERE TO SEE?
IT'S METAL.
BIG WHOOP.
JUST FIND THE AIRBENDER,
AND LET'S GET MOVING.
AND DON'T TELL ANYONE
I'M HERE.
- WHY NOT?
- I DON'T NEED TO EXPLAIN MYSELF
TO YOU.
JUST DO WHAT I SAY.
- FINE.
YOU GOT IT, CHIEF CRANKY PANTS.
- AVATAR KORRA,
IT IS AN HONOR TO MEET YOU.
MY NAME IS AIWEI.
- THANKS FOR HAVING US.
- IS THIS EVERYONE?
- YEP, JUST US.
SO CAN I MEET THE NEW AIRBENDER?
- OF COURSE.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
- AND THIS IS
THE AIR ACOLYTE DINING HALL,
WHERE EVERYONE EATS,
AND THIS IS DAW.
HE'S A NEW AIRBENDER TOO,
LIKE YOU GUYS.
- [gasps]
IT'S SO NICE TO MEET YOU.
HOW EXCITING.
NEW FRIENDS.
- EXCUSE ME, HELLO?
MY NAME IS YORRU.
I HEARD THIS WAS THE PLACE TO
COME IF YOU'RE A NEW AIRBENDER.
- YOU GOT THAT RIGHT,
STRANGER.
- WELL, A COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO,
I WOKE UP, AND SUDDENLY,
I COULD DO THIS.
- MOM, AUNT KYA,
WE GOT ANOTHER ONE!
- THAT STATUE HONORS
THE FIRST METALBENDER,
TOPH BEIFONG,
WHO EXPANDED
THE POSSIBILITIES
OF WHAT BENDERS WERE CAPABLE OF.
HERE, EVERYONE IS ENCOURAGED
TO REACH
HIS OR HER HIGHEST POTENTIAL.
- DOES TOPH LIVE HERE?
ARE WE GONNA GET TO MEET HER?
- I'M AFRAID NOT.
SHE USED TO VISIT
FROM TIME TO TIME,
BUT YEARS AGO,
SHE LEFT TO WANDER THE WORLD
IN SEARCH OF ENLIGHTENMENT.
NO ONE HAS SEEN HER SINCE.
- WOW, IS THIS
WHERE THE AIRBENDER LIVES?
- YES, BUT FIRST,
HER MOTHER WANTS TO MEET YOU.
- IS THIS SOME KIND
OF COMBAT TRAINING?
- NOT EXACTLY.
THEY ARE REHEARSING
FOR A DANCE PREMIERE NEXT MONTH.
- THAT'S IT FOR TODAY,
EVERYONE.
- ALLOW ME TO INTRODUCE
THE MATRIARCH OF THE METAL CLAN,
SUYIN.
- PLEASE, CALL ME SU.
GREAT TO FINALLY MEET YOU,
AVATAR KORRA.
AND THIS MUST BE
MAKO, BOLIN, AND ASAMI.
- YOU'VE DONE YOUR RESEARCH.
- I MAKE IT MY BUSINESS TO KNOW
WHO'S VISITING MY CITY.
- SO YOU'RE A DANCER?
- DANCER, LEADER,
WIFE, MOTHER,
COLLECTOR OF RARE METEORITES.
YOU'LL FIND PEOPLE HERE
HAVE MANY SKILLS AND INTERESTS.
- [whispering]
- KORRA, WHY DID YOU LIE
WHEN AIWEI ASKED IF THERE WAS
ANYONE ELSE WITH YOU?
- WHAT?
I-I DIDN'T.
I MEAN...
- [whimpers]
- HOW DID YOU KNOW
I WAS LYING?
- I AM A TRUTH SEER.
WHEN PEOPLE LIE,
THEIR HEART RATE
AND BREATHING INCREASE.
I CAN SENSE
THE MOST SUBTLE OF CHANGES.
- THANKS TO AIWEI, THERE ARE
NO SECRETS IN OUR CITY.
- WE CAME WITH
REPUBLIC CITY'S CHIEF OF POLICE.
SHE DIDN'T WANT ANYONE
TO KNOW SHE WAS HERE.
I'M SORRY I DIDN'T TELL YOU.
- LIN'S HERE?
WELL, I WOULD LOVE TO SAY HELLO.
- WAIT, YOU TWO
KNOW EACH OTHER?
- YOU'RE JOKING, RIGHT?
OH, LIN NEVER TOLD YOU
ABOUT ME.
- NO.
WHY WOULD SHE?
- I'M LIN'S SISTER.
- I FOUND OUT WHY
YOU WERE SO AGAINST COMING HERE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU EVER TELL ME
YOU HAD A SISTER?
- HALF-SISTER.
- SAME MOM, DIFFERENT DADS.
SO WHAT?
WE'RE BLOOD, LIN.
AND AFTER 30 YEARS, THE LEAST
YOU COULD DO IS SAY HELLO.
- I HAVE NOTHING
TO SAY TO YOU.
- YOU TWO HAVEN'T SPOKEN
IN 30 YEARS--HOW COME?
- ASK HER.
I'VE TRIED.
- OH, DON'T PUT THAT ON ME.
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO TORE OUR FAMILY APART.
- AND YOU'VE DONE A BANG-UP JOB
KEEPING IT THAT WAY.
- YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED ONE BIT,
HAVE YOU?
- LOOK, WE CAN STAND HERE
ARGUING ABOUT THE PAST ALL DAY,
BUT THAT'S NOT THE REASON
THE AVATAR CAME HERE.
MY DAUGHTER IS THRILLED
TO MEET YOU.
- LIN, YOUR NIECE
IS THE NEW AIRBENDER.
ISN'T THAT AMAZING?
- YEAH. TERRIFIC.
- THOSE ARE MY TWO YOUNGEST,
WEI AND WING.
THEY'RE PLAYING A GAME CALLED
POWER DISC.
THEY INVENTED IT
ALL ON THEIR OWN.
- YAH!
[metal clangs]
- [grunts]
- [groans]
[buzzer]
- OH, NICE POWER, WEI.
- [groans]
- HA!
WING GOES DOWN.
- I'M SO PROUD OF THOSE TWO.
[metal creaks]
HUAN, I WANT YOU TO MEET
THE AVATAR AND HER FRIENDS
AND YOUR AUNT LIN.
- NICE TO MEET YOU.
- HEY.
- WOW,
THAT'S A REALLY NICE...BANANA?
YES, VERY, VERY LIFELIKE.
- [sighs]
IT'S NOT A BANANA!
I WAS INSPIRED
BY HARMONIC CONVERGENCE.
IT REPRESENTS THE DAWNING
OF A NEW AGE, OBVIOUSLY.
- OH, YEAH, NO, I C--
I CAN TOTALLY SEE THAT.
I--WAIT, LET ME STAND HERE.
YES, I CAN SEE THAT NOW.
YES. THANK YOU.
[murmurs] BANANA.
I MEAN, THAT'S A BANANA, RIGHT?
- AND THIS IS
MY DAUGHTER OPAL.
- WOW, AVATAR KORRA.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU'RE REALLY HERE.
YOU ARE SO AMAZING.
- IT'S GREAT
TO MEET YOU, OPAL.
- OPAL?
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL NAME.
- THANKS.
- I'M BOLIN.
- OPAL, BUT, UH,
YOU ALREADY KNEW THAT.
- GREAT.
WE FOUND THE AIRBENDER.
LET'S TAKE HER BACK TO
THE AIRSHIP AND GET OUT OF HERE.
- AND THE WOMAN APPARENTLY
TRYING TO ABDUCT YOU
IS YOUR AUNT LIN.
- REALLY?
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO MEET YOU.
MY MOM HAS TOLD ME
SO MANY STORIES ABOUT YOU.
- I'M SURE SHE HAS.
- SO I'VE SET ALL OF YOU UP
IN THE GUESTHOUSES
WHILE KORRA TRAINS OPAL.
- OH, I'M SORRY,
BUT I WAS HOPING
SHE COULD TRAIN
WITH THE REST OF THE AIRBENDERS
AT THE NORTHERN TEMPLE.
- THAT SOUNDS AMAZING.
- NONSENSE.
THIS IS WHERE OPAL'S HOME
AND FAMILY ARE.
YOU CAN TRAIN HER HERE.
- I GUESS
I COULD HELP HER GET STARTED.
- ABSOLUTELY NOT.
WE'RE LEAVING.
- SHE'S JUST A LITTLE WORRIED
BECAUSE THERE ARE A BUNCH
OF CRAZY CRIMINALS AFTER ME.
- IF YOU'RE CONCERNED
ABOUT SECURITY, DON'T BE.
THIS IS THE SAFEST CITY
IN THE WORLD.
NOW, I'LL SEE YOU ALL AT DINNER,
AND COME HUNGRY.
MY CHEF WILL BLOW THE TASTE BUDS
RIGHT OUT OF YOUR MOUTH.
- WHY DO YOU HAVE SUCH A PROBLEM
WITH YOUR SISTER?
SHE SEEMS NICE.
COME ON,
WE CAN STAY A LITTLE WHILE.
- [grumbles]
- OKAY, LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU GOT.
- I'M NOT VERY GOOD.
- THAT'S OKAY.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
A TEACHER BEFORE,
SO WE'RE IN THE SAME BOAT.
YOU WANNA KEEP YOUR ELBOWS IN,
TORSO STRAIGHT,
FEET JUST SKIMMING THE GROUND.
WHY DON'T YOU
TRY IT WITH ME?
WOW,
YOU'RE A NATURAL.
- YOU REALLY THINK SO?
THANKS.
- [grunts]
- YOU CALL YOURSELF
AN AIRBENDER?
DISGRACEFUL!
- [groans]
- BE THE LEAF!
- BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS!
- NOW THAT MAN'S A LEAF.
- THE STUDENT IS
ONLY AS GOOD AS HIS MASTER.
[Poki grumbles]
- GREAT NEWS.
I JUST GOT A MESSAGE
FROM TENZIN.
HE'S WITH A WHOLE GROUP
OF OTHER AIRBENDERS
AT THE NORTHERN TEMPLE, AND HE
WANTS ALL OF YOU TO JOIN THEM.
WE LEAVE FIRST THING
IN THE MORNING.
- AND THE AVATAR IS WITH THEM?
- NO, APPARENTLY SHE HAD
TO SPLIT OFF FROM TENZIN.
- THAT'S UNFORTUNATE.
I WAS REALLY LOOKING FORWARD
TO MEETING HER.
[metal creaks]
- TONIGHT,
FOR YOUR DINING PLEASURE,
I PRESENT A SEARED WILD KYOSHI
ELEPHANT KOI,
PAIRED WITH A GINGER-INFUSED
PEA TENDRIL
AND HIBISCUS ROOT SALAD.
- STUNNING.
- SORRY, DEAR, I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO TAKE DINNER IN MY OFFICE.
I JUST HAD A MAJOR BREAKTHROUGH
ON THE TRAM STATION REMODEL.
- WELL, DON'T LET ME
STAND IN THE WAY OF INSPIRATION.
- YOU'RE THE BEST.
- THAT WAS MY BRILLIANT
ARCHITECT OF A HUSBAND, BAATAR,
AND OUR OLDEST SON.
HE ENGINEERS
ALL MY HUSBAND'S PROJECTS.
- FIVE KIDS.
WHAT A NIGHTMARE.
- NO, NO,
MY CHILDREN ARE A BLESSING.
- YEAH,
MOM USED TO SAY THAT TOO,
BUT SHE NEVER MEANT IT.
- MMM.
I HAVE TO ADMIT,
I WAS PRETTY SKEPTICAL
WHEN HE SAID "PEA TENDRIL..."
[laughs]
BUT THIS IS DELICIOUS!
- [giggles]
I KNOW, RIGHT?
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER HAD
A BAD MEAL IN MY LIFE.
- OH, I HAD PLENTY
WHEN MAKO AND I
WERE LIVING ON THE STREETS.
I MEAN, YOU'D BE SURPRISED HOW
BAD FOOD FROM A DUMPSTER CAN BE.
- I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
- NO, IT'S OKAY, IT'S OKAY.
THAT'S ALL IN THE PAST.
THINGS ARE GREAT NOW.
I GOT TO BE A PRO BENDER,
FOUGHT AGAINST
A DANGEROUS REVOLUTION,
BECAME A MOVER STAR,
AND NOW I'M HELPING THE AVATAR
REBUILD A WHOLE NATION.
- WOW, YOUR LIFE
SOUNDS SO EXCITING.
- HOW'S YOUR SEARCH
FOR THE NEW AIRBENDERS GOING?
- HONESTLY, NOT GREAT.
WE HAD TO RESCUE A WHOLE GROUP
OF THEM FROM THE EARTH QUEEN.
- OH, SHE'S HORRIBLE.
SHE THINKS SHE CAN
JUST DO WHATEVER SHE WANTS.
- SOUNDS FAMILIAR.
- WHAT?
- NOTHING.
- I MEAN, THE IDEA
OF EVEN HAVING A QUEEN
IS SO OUTDATED--
DON'T YOU AGREE, KORRA?
- I HAVEN'T REALLY THOUGHT
ABOUT IT TOO MUCH.
- WELL, YOU SHOULD START.
THE WORLD IS EVOLVING,
AND THE EARTH QUEEN
CAN EVOLVE WITH IT
OR STEP ASIDE.
- HEY, EVERYONE,
MY LITTLE SISTER IS AN EXPERT
ON WORLD AFFAIRS NOW.
- YOU WANNA TALK
ABOUT WHAT'S REALLY BUGGING YOU?
BECAUSE I'M RIGHT HERE.
- SORRY WE'RE LATE, EVERYONE.
- [gasps]
VARRICK!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- GREAT QUESTION, ASAMI.
I MEAN,
WHAT ARE ANY OF US DOING HERE?
WOW.
FOOD FOR THOUGHT.
ANYHOO,
HOW'S OUR COMPANY DOING?
- YOU MEAN MY COMPANY?
FUTURE INDUSTRIES
REVERTED BACK TO ME
AFTER YOU PLOTTED
TO ABDUCT THE PRESIDENT.
- ALLEGEDLY PLOTTED
NEVER CONVICTED.
- UH, THAT'S BECAUSE
YOU ESCAPED PRISON.
- NO, THE UNIVERSE
DECIDED TO SET ME FREE.
SO I LOOKED UP
MY OLD FRIEND SUYIN HERE,
PITCHED HER A FEW IDEAS,
AND BAM!
WE'RE IN BUSINESS TOGETHER.
- VARRICK'S HEADING UP
MY NEW TECHNOLOGY DIVISION.
- I'VE SEEN THE FUTURE,
AND THE FUTURE IS MAGNETS!
I'M WORKING
ON A HIGH-SPEED RAIL
THAT'LL REVOLUTIONIZE
TRANSPORTATION
AND SHIPPING AS WE KNOW IT.
BUT THAT'S NOT ALL!
I'M--
- ALL RIGHT, ENOUGH!
I'M TRYING TO KEEP
THE AVATAR SAFE,
AND YOU'RE HARBORING
A CRIMINAL?
- EASE UP, LIN.
SURE, VARRICK'S MADE
A FEW MISTAKES IN HIS PAST,
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN HE SHOULD
PAY FOR IT THE REST OF HIS LIFE.
MY CHEF WAS A PIRATE,
BUT NOW HE'S A CULINARY MASTER.
PEOPLE CHANGE.
- YOU HAVEN'T.
- LIN!
- SO YOU AND OPAL
SEEMED TO HIT IT OFF AT DINNER.
I THINK
SHE'S REALLY INTO YOU.
- YEAH, YOU KNOW, SHE'S SWEET
AND PRETTY AND SUPER NICE.
TOO BAD SHE'S NOT MY TYPE.
- RIGHT, I FORGOT.
YOUR TYPE IS DUMB MOVER STAR
OR PSYCHO ICE PRINCESS.
- [spits]
YOU KNOW,
THAT HURTS A LITTLE BIT.
RIGHT...HERE.
BUT MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT, BRO.
MAYBE OPAL
IS BOLIN MATERIAL.
THANKS.
YEAH!
- YOU KNOW,
BEFORE I BUILT THIS CITY,
THERE WAS NOTHING HERE.
I WANTED TO MAKE MY MARK
ON THE WORLD.
- IT'S AMAZING.
THANK YOU FOR BEING
SO WELCOMING,
AND I'M SORRY
FOR HOW LIN'S BEEN ACTING.
CAN I ASK,
WHAT HAPPENED WITH YOU TWO?
- IT'S COMPLICATED.
WE DIDN'T HAVE
A NORMAL CHILDHOOD.
NEITHER OF US
KNEW OUR FATHERS,
AND TOPH WAS ALWAYS BUSY BEING
CHIEF OF POLICE.
BECAUSE MOM GREW UP
IN SUCH A STRICT HOUSE,
SHE GAVE US
ALL THE FREEDOM IN THE WORLD,
HOPING WE'D FIGURE OUT
OUR OWN PATHS.
- THAT SOUNDS LIKE
A GOOD THING.
- AND IN A WAY, IT WAS.
BUT WE BOTH ENDED UP FIGHTING
FOR MOM'S ATTENTION.
LIN FOLLOWED IN HER FOOTSTEPS
AND BECAME A COP.
I WAS MORE OF A REBEL.
MOM WASN'T TOO HAPPY WITH
HOW EITHER OF US TURNED OUT.
WHEN I WAS 16, I LEFT HOME
TO EXPLORE THE WORLD.
I SAILED THE SEAS
ON A PIRATE SHIP,
JOINED A TRAVELING CIRCUS
FOR A WHILE,
AND LIVED IN A SANDBENDER
COMMUNE IN THE DESERT.
IT TOOK ME A WHILE,
BUT I FINALLY REALIZED
WHAT I WAS LOOKING FOR
WAS A FAMILY.
SO I BOUGHT
THIS PLOT OF LAND,
FOUND A BRILLIANT ARCHITECT
WHO LATER BECAME MY HUSBAND,
AND CREATED A PLACE
I COULD TRULY CALL HOME.
- IT SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE CREATED
THE PERFECT LIFE HERE.
- ALMOST.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED LIN
TO BE A PART OF IT,
BUT I GAVE UP HOPE LONG AGO
OF HER EVER COMING AROUND.
- HEY, LITTLE LADY.
WOW, YOU'RE REALLY BLOWING ME
AWAY WITH YOUR AIRBENDING.
[imitates whooshing]
- WHY ARE YOU ACTING WEIRD?
- WHY ARE YOU
ACTING WEIRD?
- I DON'T LIKE
HOW YOU'RE TALKING TO ME.
- LOOK, I'M SORRY.
I JUST GET REALLY SELF-CONSCIOUS
WHEN I KNOW A GIRL LIKES ME,
AND I END UP ACTING STUPID.
- WHO SAID I LIKED YOU?
- OH, NO!
BUT I THOUGHT--MAKO SAID--
- JUST KIDDING.
BUT DO ME A FAVOR
AND STOP TRYING.
WELL, DON'T STOP TRYING.
JUST STOP TRYING SO MUCH.
JUST BE YOURSELF.
- HUH, BE MYSELF.
YEAH, I GUESS
I COULD GIVE THAT A SHOT.
- [clears throat]
- OH, HEY, KORRA.
- CAN I STEAL YOU AWAY
FROM BOLIN FOR A MINUTE?
I NEED YOUR HELP
WITH SOMETHING.
- "LET GO YOUR EARTHLY TETHER.
"ENTER THE VOID.
EMPTY AND BECOME WIND."
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
NO ONE'S ALLOWED
IN DADDY'S STUDY EXCEPT DADDY.
- I'M SORRY.
I COULDN'T SLEEP.
- WHAT WERE YOU READING?
- A POEM BY GURU LAGHIMA,
THE WISEST AIRBENDER
WHO EVER LIVED.
[footsteps approaching]
- IKKI, YOU SHOULD BE IN BED.
COME ON.
- NIGHT.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- YOU SEEM TO KNOW A LOT
ABOUT AIRBENDER HISTORY
FOR SOMEONE
WHO JUST GOT AIRBENDING.
- I'VE ALWAYS ADMIRED
THE CULTURE.
- AND YOU MOVED THROUGH
THOSE GATES LIKE A NATURAL.
WHERE DID YOU SAY
YOU WERE FROM?
- A SMALL VILLAGE UP NORTH.
YOU'VE PROBABLY
NEVER HEARD OF IT.
- WAIT.
ZAHEER!
I NEED SOME HELP!
- [grunts]
[groans]
- HOLD IT RIGHT THERE!
[both grunt]
- [groans]
- SORRY I WON'T BE JOINING YOU
AT THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
I'M AFRAID
I HAVE OTHER PLANS.
[knocks on door]
- WHO IS IT?
- HEY, IT'S ME.
I BROUGHT SOMEONE
WHO WANTS TO TALK TO YOU.
- YOU WANNA TALK,
THEN TALK.
- I'M SORRY BEING HERE
HAS BEEN SO HARD FOR YOU.
WHEN YOU SHOWED UP, I WAS
SO EXCITED TO GET TO KNOW YOU.
I'D HEARD
SO MANY GREAT THINGS ABOUT YOU
FROM MOM AND GRANDMA TOPH.
SO I GUESS
I WAS KIND OF SAD
THAT YOU DIDN'T
WANNA GET TO KNOW ME.
BELIEVE ME, I KNOW MY FAMILY
CAN BE A LITTLE CRAZY
AND OVERWHELMING SOMETIMES,
BUT I WOULD LOVE IT SO MUCH
IF YOU WOULD BE A PART OF IT.
- GET OUT.
- SORRY.
DID I SAY SOMETHING WRONG?
- GET OUT!
- WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM?
DON'T GET MAD AT OPAL.
I ASKED HER TO TALK TO YOU
BECAUSE I THOUGHT
IT WOULD HELP YOU
SNAP OUT OF WHATEVER FUNK
YOU'RE IN,
BUT I GUESS I WAS WRONG.
- WHY DON'T YOU FOCUS
ON FIXING THE WORLD
AND STOP TRYING
TO FIX MY FAMILY?
- SU'S RIGHT.
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA CHANGE.
YOU'RE ALWAYS GONNA BE
A BITTER, LONELY WOMAN.
[door closes]