- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- LIN BEIFONG HAS A SISTER.
AFTER ARRIVING IN ZAOFU,
KORRA MET OPAL,
A NEW AIRBENDER, WHOSE MOTHER
IS LIN'S ESTRANGED HALF-SISTER.
SUYIN AND HER DAUGHTER
WELCOMED LIN WITH OPEN ARMS,
BUT SHE WANTED NOTHING TO DO
WITH THEM.
MEANWHILE, ZAHEER
INFILTRATED AIR TEMPLE ISLAND
LOOKING FOR THE AVATAR.
AFTER BATTLING WITH KYA,
HE ESCAPED
AND IS NOW A WANTED MAN
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
- HEY, HAS ANYONE SEEN
CHIEF BEIFONG?
- SHE'S PROBABLY OFF SULKING
IN HER ROOM.
- I KNOW SHE HAS A PROBLEM
WITH ME,
BUT SHE HAD NO RIGHT TO YELL
AT OPAL LAST NIGHT.
[footsteps approaching]
ALL SET FOR YOUR POWER DISC GAME
TODAY, GUYS?
- YEAH, ALL SET
TO KICK WEI'S BUTT.
- I'M GOING TO POWER DISC
YOUR FACE.
- [grunts, gulps]
- YOU SHOULD COME PLAY WITH US.
- OH, I DON'T THINK
I'D BE MUCH COMPETITION
SINCE I CAN'T METALBEND.
- REALLY?
LIN NEVER OFFERED
TO TRAIN YOU?
- NOPE, AND I GUESS
I NEVER THOUGHT TO BRING IT UP
BECAUSE I WAS LEARNING
TO AIRBEND,
THEN THERE WAS
THE PRO-BENDING,
THEN I GOT TIED UP
FIGHTING THE EQUALISTS.
IT WAS A BUSY FEW MONTHS.
- WELL, IT'S PROBABLY
FOR THE BEST.
I'M SURE LIN WOULD BE
A HORRIBLE TEACHER.
[chuckles]
- [laughs]
- AS THE AVATAR, YOU SHOULD HAVE
MASTERY OVER ALL THE ELEMENTS.
I'D BE HAPPY TO SHOW YOU
THE BASICS.
- REALLY?
THAT WOULD BE GREAT.
- YOU SHOULD TRY IT TOO.
- [gulps]
UH, NAH,
I'M MORE OF AN EARTH GUY.
THE DIRT, ROCKS, YOU KNOW,
MAYBE SOME LIGHT GRAVEL--
THAT'S KIND OF
WHERE MY HEART IS.
- OKAY, EARTH GUY.
WELL, LET ME KNOW
IF YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND.
[power humming]
[metallic clattering]
- [grunts]
- AAH!
- IT WORKED!
ZHU-LI, MARK IT DOWN.
MAGNET SUIT TEST SUCCESSFUL.
POWER DOWN.
ON TO PHASE TWO--
ZHU-LI CLEANS UP THIS MESS.
- HOW MANY PUSH-UPS
DID YOU DO LAST NIGHT?
'CAUSE I DID, LIKE, 50.
- WHAT DO YOU TWO
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
GET BACK TO WORK.
[groans]
- IS EVERYTHING
ALL RIGHT HERE?
- THE AVATAR IS IN DANGER,
AND THESE TWO KNUCKLEHEADS
ARE JUST STANDING AROUND
CHITCHATTING.
- DON'T WORRY.
ZAOFU IS THE MOST SECURE CITY
IN THE WORLD.
- I'LL BE THE JUDGE OF THAT.
I'M GOING TO CHECK EVERY INCH
OF THIS PLACE.
- LIN, YOU DO NOT HAVE TO WORK
WHILE YOU ARE HERE.
YOU NEED TO RELAX.
- I'M FINE!
[groans]
- DOESN'T TAKE A TRUTHSEER
TO KNOW
THAT YOU ARE UNDER
A DANGEROUS AMOUNT OF STRESS.
IF YOU DON'T DEAL
WITH YOUR REPRESSED FEELINGS,
THERE WILL BE SEVERE
CONSEQUENCES TO YOUR HEALTH
AND YOUR JOB.
- I'M NOT INTERESTED IN TALKING
ABOUT MY FEELINGS.
- YOU WON'T HAVE
TO SAY A WORD.
I KNOW A GREAT ACUPUNCTURIST
IN TOWN
WHO WILL BE ABLE
TO HELP YOU.
- HMM.
[siren wails in the distance]
- SEEMS LIKE YOU MADE QUITE
A STIR ON AIR TEMPLE ISLAND.
THE COPS ARE SWARMING THE CITY
LOOKING FOR US.
- YOU STILL WANT TO TRY
TO TAKE OUT THE PRESIDENT?
- NO.
HE'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
WE LEAVE TODAY.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
THERE'S OUR TICKET
OUT OF HERE.
- [grunts]
[grunts, whimpering]
THERE'S NO MONEY.
I JUST MADE MY LAST DELIVERY.
- WE DON'T WANT MONEY.
[gentle music]
♪ ♪
- HOW MANY OF THOSE THINGS
ARE YOU GONNA STICK IN ME?
- I'LL BE PLACING
SEVERAL NEEDLES
ON EACH OF YOUR ACUPOINTS.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE SCARED ABOUT.
- I'M NOT AFRAID OF NEEDLES!
- PLEASE CLOSE YOUR EYES
AND TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
- [breathes deeply]
- THIS PROCESS WILL CORRECT
THE IMBALANCES
IN YOUR CHI.
PLEASE TELL ME IF YOU FEEL
ANY PAIN OR PRESSURE.
- I CAN'T FEEL A THING.
- THAT'S UNUSUAL.
YOUR CHI MUST BE
POWERFULLY BLOCKED.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
MORE NEEDLES.
ACUPUNCTURE OFTEN TAPS
INTO PEOPLE'S BURIED MEMORIES.
THESE MEMORIES CAN SOMETIMES BE
DIFFICULT TO PROCESS.
- [scoffs]
BURIED MEMORIES, UH-HUH.
[door opens]
SU, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HOME?
- [laughs]
WOW.
YOU ALMOST LOOK LIKE
A REAL COP.
- YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
IN SCHOOL.
- OH, NO.
ARE YOU GONNA TELL MOM?
IT'S NOT LIKE
SHE'S GOING TO CARE.
- WHERE'D YOU GET
ALL THAT STUFF?
- UH, FELL OFF THE BACK
OF A TRUCK.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING
HANGING OUT WITH THESE LOSERS?
- THEY'RE MY FRIENDS, AND YOU
HAVE NO RIGHT TO CALL THEM THAT!
[scoffs] COME ON, GUYS,
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
- SU, STOP!
- GET YOUR HANDS OFF OF ME!
- YOU HAVE SO MUCH POTENTIAL.
YOU'RE RUINING YOUR LIFE.
- AT LEAST I HAVE A LIFE.
- [murmuring]
- THESE METEORITES ARE PERFECT
FOR BEGINNING METALBENDERS.
THE METALS HAVE
A UNIQUE PROPERTY,
MAKING THEM EASIER TO BEND.
- THAT'S AMAZING.
- HERE, TRY IT.
- OKAY.
[majestic music]
♪ ♪
[twig snaps]
[Pabu chirps]
BOLIN, IS THAT YOU?
- NO.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- OH, HEY, LADIES.
I WAS JUST, UH--
I WAS JUST LOOKING FOR PABU.
PABU!
- HE'S ON YOUR SHOULDER.
- OH, LOOK,
THERE YOU ARE.
YOU KNOW, I THOUGHT
SOMETHING WAS CHEWING ON MY EAR.
I'M PROBABLY GONNA NEED
TO GET A SHOT.
PABU HAS SORT OF A VENOM--
A VENOM.
ANYWAY, SO WHAT ARE
YOU GUYS DOING?
YOU'RE METALBENDING OVER HERE
OR SOMETHING?
- WANT TO GIVE IT A SHOT?
- NAH, IT'S OKAY.
I MEAN, ONLY, LIKE,
ONE EARTHBENDER IN A HUNDRED
CAN METALBEND.
- WELL, DON'T BELIEVE
EVERYTHING YOU HEAR.
THE ONLY THING LIMITING YOU
IS YOUR ATTITUDE.
- YOU KNOW, WELL,
MAYBE I'LL JUST--
I'LL JUST STAY AND WATCH.
[majestic music]
♪ ♪
- TRY TO FOCUS
ON THE FINE PIECES OF EARTH
WITHIN THE METAL.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I'M METALBENDING!
- WOW, YOU PICKED THAT UP
REALLY, REALLY QUICK.
I GUESS YOU'RE THAT ONE
IN A HUNDRED.
- GREAT JOB, KORRA.
- CALLING ALL UNITS.
ROBBERY REPORTED ON THE CORNER
OF FIFTH AND HARBOR.
SUSPECTS' VEHICLE HEADED SOUTH
ON HAO BOULEVARD.
UNITS RESPONDING, IDENTIFY.
- UNIT THREE RESPONDING.
[tires squealing,
siren wailing]
[people screaming]
[overlapping shouting]
[both shout]
- LEAVE THEM ALONE!
- SU?
[gasps]
[panting]
- WAIT.
LEAVING IN THE MIDDLE OF
A SESSION COULD MAKE YOU SICK.
- I'M DONE HERE.
[groaning]
[door opens]
- ARE YOU GONNA STAY
IN YOUR ROOM
FEELING SORRY FOR YOURSELF
ALL DAY?
YOU OWE OPAL AN APOLOGY...
- FOR THE WAY YOU TREATED HER
LAST NIGHT.
ARE YOU OKAY?
YOU DON'T LOOK GOOD.
- I'M FINE.
[groans]
[grunts]
WHAT DID YOU DO TO ME?
- I TRIED TO WARN YOU.
COME WITH ME.
LET'S GO FINISH THE SESSION.
JUST RELAX AND BREATHE.
- SO YOU'RE ROBBING STORES
WITH THE TERRA TRIAD NOW?
- I DIDN'T STEAL ANYTHING.
I JUST DROVE THE CAR.
I OWED MY FRIENDS A FAVOR.
IT'S NOT A BIG DEAL.
- I'M NOT LETTING YOU
GET AWAY WITH THIS.
- [laughs]
OH.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO,
OFFICER, ARREST ME?
- DON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT TAKING
ONE MORE STEP!
[screams]
[groaning]
- GOOD AFTERNOON.
WHERE ARE YOU OFF TO TODAY?
- I, UH, GOT A DELIVERY TO MAKE
IN BAO YU.
I SHOULD BE BACK
LATER TODAY.
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YEAH, JUST A LITTLE TIRED.
ONE MORE PICKUP,
THEN I'M CLOCKING OUT.
- I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU HAD A DELIVERY.
- DID I?
- I'M GONNA NEED YOU
TO STEP OUT OF THE VEHICLE
AND OPEN THE BACK
OF THE TRUCK.
[truck door opens]
- [screams]
- HEY, GET BACK HERE!
- LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
[tires squealing]
[siren wailing]
- [whistling]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
HMM, HMM.
[sighs]
- HEY, BOLIN.
- [gasps]
OPAL!
OH, WOW.
YOU REALLY KNOW HOW TO SNEAK UP
ON SOMEONE.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- OH, NOTHING,
YOU KNOW, JUST--
JUST THINKING ABOUT MY BODY
AND MUSTACHES THAT I MIGHT HAVE
IN THE FUTURE.
- YOU'RE ACTING WEIRD AGAIN.
- SORRY.
[sighs]
I WASN'T REALLY THINKING
ABOUT ALL MY MUSTACHES.
I'M JUST--
I'M JUST FRUSTRATED.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO METALBEND,
AND I CAN'T FIGURE IT OUT.
[sighs]
DON'T TELL ANYONE, OKAY?
- WHY NOT?
- BECAUSE IT'S EMBARRASSING.
THIS ISN'T THE FIRST TIME
I'VE TRIED.
I MEAN, I'VE BEEN WANTING
TO METALBEND
EVER SINCE I HEARD ABOUT TOPH.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER
IS MY BIGGEST HERO.
- MY MOM GREW UP
LEARNING FROM TOPH.
JUST GO TRAIN WITH HER.
STOP BEING SO SCARED.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
MAYBE I AM SCARED,
BUT WHAT ABOUT YOU?
I KNOW THAT YOU WANT TO GO
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE
TO TRAIN WITH TENZIN,
BUT YOU HAVEN'T DONE IT
BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID TOO.
- YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DON'T WANT TO LEAVE MY FAMILY
AND DISAPPOINT MY MOM.
- LOOK AT US...
TALKING ABOUT OUR FEELINGS,
SUPPORTING EACH OTHER.
- IT'S NICE.
- WHAT WERE YOU THINKING?
AND WHAT WERE YOU THINKING?
YOU TWO HAVE PUT ME
IN AN IMPOSSIBLE POSITION.
- YOU'RE MAD AT ME?
SHE'S THE ONE WHO WAS
RUNNING AROUND WITH CRIMINALS.
- THIS IS ALL YOUR FAULT!
- I WAS DOING MY JOB!
- UGH, ALL RIGHT, ENOUGH!
HERE'S WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO.
SU, YOU NEED TO LEAVE THE CITY
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
- WHAT?
WHERE AM I SUPPOSED TO GO?
- YOU'LL GO STAY
WITH YOUR GRANDPARENTS.
LIN, GIVE ME
THE ARREST REPORT.
[paper tears]
- MOM, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU CAN'T COVER THIS UP.
THERE WERE WITNESSES.
- I'M THE CHIEF OF POLICE.
I CAN'T HAVE A DAUGHTER
IN JAIL.
- SO, ONCE AGAIN, SU GETS TO DO
WHATEVER SHE WANTS,
AND THERE ARE
NO CONSEQUENCES.
- [sighs]
THIS IS OUR ONLY OPTION.
- YOU'RE GOING TO FEEL
A BIT FRAGILE,
SO IT'S PROBABLY BEST IF YOU
TAKE IT EASY FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
- I DON'T NEED TO REST.
I NEED TO DO SOMETHING
I SHOULD'VE DONE
A LONG TIME AGO.
- CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU'RE THE FIRST
METALBENDING AVATAR.
- SO, UM,
I'VE BEEN THINKING,
AND I'D LIKE TO TRY
TO LEARN METALBENDING.
I MEAN, I'M SURE YOU HAVE
A WAITING LIST OR SOMETHING,
LIKE, A COUPLE YEARS, SO...
- LET'S GET STARTED.
[Pabu chirps]
- [breathing heavily]
- I THINK LIN IS MAD
ABOUT SOMETHING.
- SU, IT'S TIME WE TALK.
- AFTER 30 YEARS,
YOU'RE FINALLY READY TO TALK?
- WHEN WE WERE IN MOM'S OFFICE
THAT DAY,
YOU COULD HAVE TAKEN
RESPONSIBILITY FOR WHAT YOU DID,
BUT INSTEAD YOU STAYED QUIET
AND LET MOM
THROW HER WHOLE CAREER AWAY.
- MOM DIDN'T THROW
HER CAREER AWAY.
SHE RETIRED THE NEXT YEAR.
SHE WAS A HERO.
- YOU THINK
SHE WANTED TO RETIRE?
SHE WAS SO GUILT-RIDDEN ABOUT
WHAT SHE DID TO PROTECT YOU,
SHE DIDN'T FEEL WORTHY
OF HER BADGE.
- LOOK, I ADMIT
THAT I WAS NOT A PERFECT KID
AND I'VE MADE SOME MISTAKES
IN THE PAST, BUT--
- [scoffs]
YOU MADE SOME MISTAKES?
- LIN, MOM AND I ALREADY TALKED
ABOUT THIS YEARS AGO
AND WORKED THINGS OUT.
IF YOU HAD GOTTEN TOGETHER
WITH US LIKE WE'D ASKED,
YOU WOULD KNOW
THAT I'M A DIFFERENT PERSON NOW.
I'VE BEEN A DIFFERENT PERSON
FOR A LONG TIME.
- YOU THINK JUST BECAUSE
YOU LIVE IN A BIG, FANCY HOUSE
AND HAVE A CHEF
WHO COOKS YOU FANCY FOOD
THAT YOU'RE
A DIFFERENT PERSON?
MAYBE YOU CAN FOOL EVERYONE
ELSE, BUT YOU CAN'T FOOL ME.
I SEE RIGHT THROUGH YOU.
- YOU KNOW WHAT, LIN?
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO HASN'T CHANGED.
YOU'RE STILL A BITTER LONER
WHO ONLY CARES ABOUT HERSELF.
NO WONDER TENZIN ENDED THINGS
WITH YOU YEARS AGO.
[dramatic music]
- OKAY, I GUESS
THIS IS HOW IT'S GOING TO BE.
♪ ♪
- SHOULD I STOP THEM?
- YOU DON'T HAVE ANY SIBLINGS.
FIGHTING IS ALL PART
OF THE HEALING PROCESS.
- GO, MOM!
- [gasps]
MY SCULPTURE!
ACTUALLY, IT LOOKS
KIND OF BETTER NOW.
- [breathing heavily,
growls]
- YOU GOT IT
OUT OF YOUR SYSTEM?
- NOT QUITE YET!
- WHAT ARE YOU TWO DOING?
YOU'RE SISTERS!
WHY WOULD YOU WANT
TO HURT EACH OTHER?
- [breathing heavily]
- [breathing heavily, groans]
- UH, WHO'S GONNA KNOCK?
- OH! NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NOT ME. YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
WHY CAN'T YOU DO IT?
- UH, I CAN.
BUT I JUST THOUGHT
THAT YOU--
- I'LL DO IT.
UH, CHIEF, YOU'VE BEEN SLEEPING
FOR 16 HOURS.
WE JUST WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU'RE OKAY.
OOH!
- [yawns]
GOOD MORNING.
WHAT'S THIS?
- I CALL IT THE KALENUTSCO.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF KALE,
COCONUT WATER, AND WALNUTS.
- NOT BAD.
OPAL, DON'T GO.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
LOOK, I'M JUST NOT
REALLY COMFORTABLE
TALKING ABOUT THESE KINDS
OF THINGS,
AND, WELL...
I WANTED TO SAY I'M SORRY
ABOUT THE OTHER NIGHT.
- IT'S OKAY.
- YOUR MOTHER AND I HAVE
A COMPLICATED RELATIONSHIP AND--
- IT'S PROBABLY DIFFICULT
FOR YOU TO BE HERE.
- YOU'RE A SMART YOUNG WOMAN
AND AN EXCELLENT AIRBENDER.
I THINK IT WOULD BE A WONDERFUL
OPPORTUNITY FOR YOU TO TRAIN
WITH THE OTHER AIRBENDERS
AT THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
- THERE'S A PART OF ME
THAT WANTS TO GO,
BUT I DON'T WANT
TO UPSET MY MOM.
- WHEN I WAS YOUNGER,
ALL I WANTED TO DO
WAS PLEASE MY MOTHER.
I BECAME A POLICE CHIEF
BECAUSE I THOUGHT
IT WOULD MAKE HER HAPPY,
BUT IT DIDN'T.
YOU NEED TO MAKE DECISIONS
BASED ON WHAT YOU WANT.
DON'T MAKE THE SAME MISTAKES
I DID.
- MOM? DAD?
CAN I TALK TO YOU?
- OPAL HAS DECIDED TO GO
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
I'M GUESSING YOU HAD SOMETHING
TO DO WITH HER DECISION.
- WELL, I WAS JUST--
- IT'S OKAY.
I'M GLAD SHE WAS HONEST WITH ME.
I WANT HER TO DO
WHAT MAKES HER HAPPY.
MOM GAVE US
TOO MUCH FREEDOM,
BUT I FEEL LIKE
I'VE MADE THE MISTAKE
OF GIVING OPAL TOO LITTLE.
I THINK IT'S TIME
I LET HER CHOOSE HER OWN WAY.
I'M SORRY I GAVE YOU SUCH A HARD
TIME WHEN WE WERE YOUNGER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT MY LIFE
WOULD'VE BEEN LIKE
IF MOM HADN'T SENT ME AWAY,
IF I HAD STAYED IN THE CITY.
- YOU'D PROBABLY BE
IN PRISON.
- [chuckles]
YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
MAKO TOLD ME THAT YOU'RE
AN EXCELLENT POLICE CHIEF.
REPUBLIC CITY IS LUCKY
TO HAVE YOU.
I KNOW MOM IS PROUD.
CAN WE MOVE ON?
I'D LOVE FOR YOU TO BE
A PART OF MY LIFE AGAIN.
THERE'S PLENTY OF SPACE FOR YOU
IN THE HOUSE,
AND THE KIDS WOULD LOVE
HAVING THEIR AUNT AROUND.
I DO NEED A CODIRECTOR
FOR MY NEW DANCE PERFORMANCE.
- WHOA.
SLOW DOWN.
HOW ABOUT FOR NOW,
I JUST PROMISE
NOT TO SHOW UP AT YOUR HOUSE
AND ATTACK YOU AGAIN?
- DEAL.
- WE SHOULD'VE GRABBED
ONE OF THOSE COPS.
MAYBE THEY KNOW SOMETHING ABOUT
WHERE THE AVATAR IS HIDING.
- SHE COULD BE ANYWHERE.
- WE'LL FIND HER.
IT'S JUST A MATTER OF TIME.
- SHE'S WITH THE METAL CLAN.