- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
- THE AIR NATION IS REBORN!
THANKS TO THE ENERGY SHIFT
DURING HARMONIC CONVERGENCE,
CERTAIN PEOPLE HAVE ACQUIRED
AIRBENDING ABILITIES,
INCLUDING BUMI, KAI,
AND OPAL.
BUT ALTHOUGH THE NEW RECRUITS
SHOW A LOT OF PROMISE,
THEY STILL HAVE A LOT
TO LEARN.
SO WHILE KORRA REMAINS SAFE
IN ZAOFU,
TENZIN HAS BROUGHT
THE AIRBENDERS
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE
TO BEGIN THEIR TRAINING.
- HIS PUPILS ONCE AGAIN PLEADED
WITH THEIR MASTER
TO EAT SOMETHING,
BUT HE REFUSED,
JUST LIKE HE HAD EACH DAY
THE ENTIRE SUMMER.
INSTEAD, HE SIMPLY MEDITATED,
GETTING HIS NOURISHMENT
FROM THE UNIVERSE.
SO MONK TANG XU COMPLETED
THE 97TH DAY
OF HIS HISTORIC FAST
ON WHICH ISLAND?
- OOH! OOH, OOH!
- ANYONE BESIDES OTAKU,
WHO ALREADY STUDIED THIS
IN HIS ACOLYTE TRAINING...
- OOH, OOH, OOH!
- AND IS ANSWERING
EVERY QUESTION?
- OOH! OOH! OOH!
WHALETAIL ISLAND!
- THAT IS CORRECT.
AGAIN.
NOW, ON DAY 98--
[laughter]
- [squeaky voice]
GREETINGS, AIR PEOPLE.
I COME SEEKING BORING STORIES
TO TAKE BACK TO THE SPIRIT
WORLD.
[shouts]
[laughter]
- [clears throat]
[inspiring music]
♪ ♪
- THAT WAS INCREDIBLE!
WHEN DO WE GET TO FLY AROUND
ON OUR OWN BISON LIKE THAT?
- ONLY AFTER MANY YEARS
OF PRACTICE
AND INTENSE TRAINING.
[students groaning]
BESIDES, WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
BISON HERE FOR ALL OF YOU.
- WHAT ABOUT THOSE?
IT'S A WHOLE HERD OF BISONS.
- ACTUALLY, THE PLURAL
OF "BISON" IS "BISON."
- [laughs]
WHOA!
- COOL!
- WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
- CAN WE RIDE THOSE?
- NO, THAT'S A WILD HERD.
IT WOULD TAKE MANY YEARS
TO TAME THEM.
NOW LET'S GET BACK
TO OUR LESSONS.
- DAD!
WE BROUGHT YOU
MORE AIRBENDERS!
[bison grunting]
- OKAY, EVERYONE IS DISMISSED.
WE'LL JUST
PICK THIS UP...
[sighs]
TOMORROW.
HOW WAS EVERYTHING
IN THE CITY?
- WELL, WE HAD A LITTLE SCARE,
BUT EVERYTHING IS OKAY.
ZAHEER INFILTRATED
THE AIR TEMPLE.
- WHAT?
IS EVERYONE ALL RIGHT?
- EVERYONE'S FINE.
I FOUGHT WITH HIM,
BUT HE GOT AWAY.
AND HE STOLE SOME OLD NECKLACE
THAT HAD SOMETHING TO DO
WITH GURU LAK...SCHMEER.
- GURU LAGHIMA.
- RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I CAN NEVER KEEP
ALL THOSE GURUS STRAIGHT.
THERE WERE, LIKE,
A MILLION OF THEM.
REMEMBER THAT LONG, BORING STORY
ABOUT THE GUY
WHO NEVER ATE?
- YES, I REMEMBER.
- AVATAR KORRA IS CALLING
ON THE TEMPLE RADIO.
[static]
- ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHERE ARE YOU?
- WITH BEIFONG'S SISTER
IN ZAOFU.
WE'RE TOTALLY SAFE,
UNLESS WE GET CAUGHT
IN ANOTHER FIGHT
BETWEEN SU AND LIN.
- LIN WILLINGLY TOOK YOU
TO HER SISTER?
- NOT EXACTLY.
WE GOT A CALL
ABOUT A NEW AIRBENDER,
AND IT TURNED OUT TO BE
SU'S DAUGHTER, OPAL.
SHE'LL BE HEADED
YOUR WAY SOON.
- REALLY?
THAT'S WONDERFUL!
- SHE IS WONDERFUL
AND PRETTY
AND SO SMART!
AND SHE SMELLS LIKE FLOWERS.
SORRY.
BOLIN OUT.
- HOW'S THE TRAINING GOING?
- NOT SO WELL, I'M AFRAID.
NO ONE SEEMS TO BE INTERESTED
IN THE HARD WORK
REQUIRED TO BECOME A PART
OF THE AIR NATION.
- YOU NEED TO GIVE YOURSELF
A BREAK.
LET JINORA AND THE KIDS
HELP YOU OUT.
AND WHAT ABOUT BUMI?
HE WAS A NAVAL COMMANDER.
MAYBE HE HAS SOME IDEAS
ABOUT HOW TO GET PEOPLE
MOTIVATED.
- BUMI?
HE'S MY WORST STUDENT!
- YEAH, BUT HE LOVES
TO ORGANIZE PEOPLE.
IF YOU ASK HIM FOR HELP,
YOU CAN TRICK HIM
INTO TAKING
MORE RESPONSIBILITY
BY MAKING HIM THINK
THE WHOLE THING WAS HIS IDEA.
- HMM.
THAT ACTUALLY SOUNDS
LIKE A GOOD PLAN.
YOU'RE TURNING INTO
A PRETTY WISE AVATAR AFTER ALL.
- CONFLICT RESOLUTION.
IT'S WHAT I DO.
- WE SHOULD GO DOWN THERE.
I WANT TO FLY
ONE OF THOSE BISONS.
- I DON'T KNOW.
WE MIGHT GET IN TROUBLE.
- COME ON,
LET'S HAVE SOME FUN.
WE'LL BE BACK BEFORE ANYONE
REALIZES WE'RE GONE.
- I GUESS IT WILL BE
ALL RIGHT.
[exciting music]
♪ ♪
- LOOK, BABY BISONS.
HOW COME THEY'RE ALL
ON THE GROUND?
- AIR BISON CALVES CAN'T FLY
FOR A WEEK OR TWO
AFTER THEY'RE BORN,
SO THE ENTIRE HERD WILL STAY
NEAR THE GROUND
IN THE VALLEY.
- LET'S GO SEE THE BABIES.
- BE CAREFUL.
THE MOTHERS ARE VERY PROTECTIVE.
[bison growling softly]
- AW, LOOK HOW CUTE.
- KAI, GET OUT OF THERE!
[bison growling aggressively]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- WHOA!
WOW, YOU REALLY SAVED ME
DOWN THERE.
- OH.
- YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE
AN INCREDIBLE AIRBENDER.
- WELL, I'VE BEEN TRAINING
FOR A LONG TIME.
- THEN WHY DON'T YOU HAVE
TATTOOS LIKE AN AIRBENDING
MASTER?
- MY DAD SAYS
I'M NOT A MASTER YET.
- YOU CAN DO EVERYTHING
YOUR DAD CAN,
PLUS YOU HAVE
ALL THOSE SPIRIT-Y POWERS.
IF ANYONE'S A MASTER,
YOU ARE.
- [chuckles]
SO WE BRING THE NET DOWN
ON THE HEAD PIRATE,
AND HE LOOKS AROUND REAL SAD
AND SAYS, "I KNEW I SHOULD HAVE
FOLLOWED MY DREAMS
AND BECOME A DENTIST."
- [laughs]
HOW COME YOU GREW UP
TO BE SO COOL,
WHILE TENZIN BECAME
SUCH A STICK IN THE MUD?
- WELL, I GUESS "COOL" IS
JUST SOMETHING YOU'RE BORN WITH.
- BUMI, CAN I TALK TO YOU?
- LET ME GUESS--YOU WANT
TO CRITICIZE ME FOR SOMETHING.
- ACTUALLY, I NEED YOUR HELP.
- OH, YEAH?
WITH WHAT?
- I DON'T THINK
I'M DOING VERY WELL
WITH THE NEW AIRBENDERS,
AND EVERYONE KNOWS
YOU'RE A NATURAL LEADER.
- TRUE, I DID WIN
THE ADMIRAL TUNG
NATURAL LEADERSHIP AWARD
TWICE.
- WHAT WOULD YOU DO
IF YOU WERE IN CHARGE?
HELP ME BE MORE LIKE YOU.
- I'D LOVE TO.
YOU'VE GOTTA USE
MILITARY DISCIPLINE
TO WHIP THESE TROOPS
INTO SHAPE.
THE ONLY WAY TO DEAL
WITH NEW RECRUITS
IS TO BREAK THEM DOWN,
SO YOU CAN BUILD THEM BACK UP.
RULE WITH AN IRON FIST.
SHOW THEM WHO THE MASTER IS.
- THANKS FOR THE INSIGHT.
- MY PLEASURE.
[horn blares]
[students groaning]
- DAWN PATROL!
EVERYONE UP!
- UGH.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IT'S BARELY LIGHT OUT.
- I'M TAKING YOUR ADVICE.
I'M GOING TO BREAK YOU DOWN
AND BUILD YOU BACK UP.
NOW GET MOVING, RECRUIT!
- [groans]
[peaceful music]
♪ ♪
- [grunts]
- [groans]
- NOTHING LIKE A 10-MILE HIKE
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
- DON'T THESE ROBES COME
IN A WARM, BISON FUR VERSION?
- NO, OF COURSE NOT!
- OH!
IF IT WEREN'T SO COLD,
I'D GO RIGHT BACK TO SLEEP.
- THEN THIS IS THE PERFECT TIME
TO LEARN MEDITATION
AND PROPER BREATHING TECHNIQUE.
AIRBENDERS ARE ABLE
TO WARM THEMSELVES
WITH ONLY THEIR BREATHING.
EVERYONE GET
INTO THE LOTUS POSITION.
AH, THIS IS SO MUCH MORE
REFRESHING THAN SLEEPING.
- YOU KNOW, WHEN I SAID
THAT THING ABOUT AN IRON FIST--
- HUSH.
MEDITATION TIME.
FOCUS.
- CAN WE GO BACK TO BED NOW?
- NOW THAT WE'RE REFRESHED
AND LOOSE
FROM OUR HIKE
AND MEDITATION,
IT'S TIME
FOR A BALANCING EXERCISE.
[air whooshes]
THE KEY IS TO MAINTAIN YOUR
HEAVEN AND EARTH CONNECTION.
NOW YOU TRY.
[students grunting]
BACK ON THE POSTS!
IT'S NOT HARD
IF YOU CONCENTRATE!
[all grunting]
- WHOA.
- UGH.
WHOA!
[grunts]
- GET BACK UP!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU CAN'T HANDLE IT, SOLDIER?
- [groans]
[squeaking]
[students grunting]
- DON'T YOU THINK YOU'RE BEING
A LITTLE HARD ON THEM?
- DON'T WORRY.
THEY CAN TAKE IT.
YOU'LL SEE.
IGNORE THE LEMURS
DIGGING IN YOUR EARS.
CONCENTRATE ON YOUR BREATHING,
AND YOU WON'T EVEN KNOW
THEY'RE THERE.
- WHOA, UH, UGH, OH!
- WHEN THE HEAD IS SHAVED,
AN AIRBENDER IS ABLE
TO FEEL THE WIND AROUND HIM.
IT IS BOTH HUMBLING
AND FREEING.
- HEY, YOU WANNA SNEAK AWAY
AND GO CHECK
ON THE BABY BISONS?
- SHH. YOU SHOULD BE
PAYING ATTENTION.
[head squeaks]
- ALL RIGHT, WHO'S NEXT?
- I'M NOT SURE I WANT
TO SHAVE MY HEAD.
- THAT'S FINE.
SHAVING YOUR HEAD
IS A PERSONAL CHOICE.
- WAIT, WHAT?
- ANYONE ELSE?
FINE, THEN WE CAN GET RIGHT
TO OUR NEXT TRAINING EXERCISE--
OBSTACLE COURSE!
[students groan]
- YOU'RE PUSHING TOO HARD.
MAYBE WE SHOULD GIVE THEM
A BREAK.
- JINORA, I HAVE THIS
UNDER CONTROL.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
CONCENTRATE.
REMEMBER, AIRBENDERS MOVE
LIKE THE WIND.
- AGH!
♪ ♪
- UGH!
- [whimpers]
♪ ♪
- STAY LIGHT ON YOUR FEET,
AND YOU'LL NEVER FEEL
THE STINGING RASH-CACTUS.
- [grunts]
- OW!
♪ ♪
- [grunting]
- EVERYONE IS WAITING
FOR YOU, BUMI.
IF YOU DON'T MAKE IT OVER
IN THE NEXT 30 SECONDS,
THEY'LL ALL HAVE TO RUN
THROUGH THE COURSE AGAIN.
- YOU CAN DO IT, BUMI!
- COME ON!
- [grunting]
AGH!
[grunting]
- GET BACK ON THAT WALL,
RECRUIT!
YOU'RE LETTING
YOUR FELLOW AIRBENDERS DOWN.
- [growls]
I'M FINISHED!
I NEVER WANTED
TO BE AN AIRBENDER,
AND I'M TOO OLD TO BE
BACK IN BOOT CAMP!
COUNT ME OUT.
- FINE, QUIT!
WE DON'T NEED YOUR ATTITUDE
IN THE NEW AIR NATION.
- MASTER TENZIN?
WHEN DO WE GET TO GO HOME
AND VISIT OUR FAMILIES?
- GO HOME?
YOU JUST GOT HERE.
- WHEN'S DINNER?
I'M STARVING.
- CAN I CHANGE
OUT OF MY ROBE NOW?
IT'S ITCHY.
- THIS IS JUST AS BAD
AS THE EARTH QUEEN'S PRISON.
- I'M TIRED
OF ALL THIS COMPLAINING.
JINORA, TAKE OVER.
- DOES THIS MEAN
I'M THE MASTER NOW?
- YES. JUST LEAD THEM
THROUGH SOME BASIC EXERCISES.
- WELL, SINCE I'M A MASTER,
WHEN DO YOU THINK I CAN GET
MY TATTOOS?
- WHAT BROUGHT THIS ON?
- I WAS JUST TALKING TO KAI,
AND HE WAS ASKING ME, SO--
- KAI! WHAT DOES HE KNOW
ABOUT WHEN
YOU SHOULD GET TATTOOS?
THE ANSWER IS NO!
YOU'RE JUST A LITTLE GIRL.
- I'M NOT
A LITTLE GIRL ANYMORE!
I CAN AIRBEND
JUST AS WELL AS YOU.
I KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT OUR CULTURE AND HISTORY,
AND I HAVE A STRONGER CONNECTION
WITH THE SPIRITS
THAN YOU EVER WILL.
LEAD YOUR OWN CLASS!
- IKKI, MEELO, YOU'RE UP.
JUST LEAD THEM
THROUGH THE BAGUA CIRCLE.
- LOOK TO YOUR LEFT!
LOOK TO YOUR RIGHT!
ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE WILL NOT
MAKE IT OUT OF HERE ALIVE.
[peaceful music]
- SORRY IF WHAT I SAID
GOT YOU IN TROUBLE
WITH YOUR DAD.
- IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
HE JUST CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT I'M GROWN UP NOW
AND I DON'T NEED HIM
TELLING ME WHAT TO DO
LIKE ONE OF HIS RECRUITS.
- I KNOW SOMETHING
THAT'LL CHEER YOU UP.
- WHERE DID
ALL THE SPIRITS GO?
- WHERE ARE THE BABIES?
[bang]
- AAH!
- [grunts]
- WHAT ARE THESE KIDS DOING
IN MY CAMP?
- WE CAUGHT THEM
SNEAKING AROUND.
WE THOUGHT THEY MIGHT
TELL SOMEONE WE'RE HERE.
- THEY'RE THOSE NEW AIRBENDERS.
MUST BE LIVING
UP AT THE TEMPLE.
HURRY UP AND GATHER
THE REST OF THE GANG,
AND LET'S GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE SOMEONE COMES LOOKING
FOR THESE KIDS.
WE'LL TAKE THEM
TO BA SING SE
WITH THE REST
OF THE FRESH MEAT.
- TATTOOS.
HOW CAN SHE THINK--
[sighs]
FOCUS.
BREATHE.
[inhales]
BUMI RUINS EVERYTHING.
INHALE.
[inhales]
FOCUS.
- TAKING A LITTLE BREAK
FROM TEACHING?
- I FAILED.
BUMI QUIT, AND THE REST
OF THE AIRBENDERS
WANT TO GO HOME.
CAN'T THEY SEE
THAT I'M TRYING
TO REBUILD
AN ENTIRE CULTURE?
- YOU KNOW, JUST BECAUSE
THESE PEOPLE CAN AIRBEND,
IT DOESN'T AUTOMATICALLY
MAKE THEM AIR NOMADS.
- TELL ME ABOUT IT.
- I REMEMBER WHEN I MOVED
OUT OF MY PARENTS' HOUSE
TO BECOME AN AIR ACOLYTE.
THAT FIRST NIGHT,
I WAS SO SCARED AND LONELY,
AND THE BED WAS SO HARD.
- IT'S ACTUALLY BETTER
FOR YOUR BACK.
SORRY.
- THE POINT IS,
I REALLY WANTED
TO BE THERE,
BUT IT STILL TOOK TIME
FOR ME TO ADJUST
AND FEEL LIKE I WAS
A PART OF IT ALL.
THESE PEOPLE ARE PROBABLY
FEELING THE SAME WAY.
YOU HAVE TO BE PATIENT.
- NOW I KNOW HOW KORRA FEELS
WHEN I'M TALKING TO HER.
THANK YOU, PEMA.
[peaceful music]
♪ ♪
BUMI, I WANT TO APOLOGIZE
FOR LOSING MY PATIENCE.
- I'M NOT TALKING TO YOU.
- [squeaks]
- HEY, GET BACK HERE!
[sighs]
WHERE'S JINORA?
- I SAW HER FLY OFF
ON HER GLIDER
WITH HER BOYFRIEND.
- WHAT? HER BOYFRIEND?
KAI.
- HOW CAN YOU STEAL
THESE BISON?
THEY'RE ENDANGERED.
- THAT'S WHY THEY'RE WORTH
SO MUCH.
THE EARTH QUEEN
AND HER FANCY FRIENDS
PAY BIG MONEY FOR BISON STEAKS
AND OTHER WEIRD MEAT.
I EVEN HEARD SHE ATE
HER DAD'S PET BEAR.
- YOU'RE DISGUSTING.
[bison whimper]
- HEY, DO THAT SPIRIT BEAMING
THING YOU DID TO FIND ME.
GO TO THE TEMPLE FOR HELP.
- I CAN'T.
I'M ALL CRAMPED IN HERE,
AND I NEED QUIET
AND TIME TO FOCUS.
BUT MAYBE I CAN SEND
A MESSAGE.
[tense music]
SPIRITS, I NEED YOUR HELP.
- [squeaking]
- GO FIND BUM-JU.
TELL HIM WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
- [squeaking]
- [squeaks]
- NO, I DON'T THINK
I SHOULD APOLOGIZE.
TENZIN JUST WANTS
TO BOSS EVERYBODY AROUND.
I'M TOO OLD FOR THAT.
- [chirping]
- WELL, LET'S FACE IT.
I'M JUST NOT CUT OUT TO BE
AN AIRBENDER.
- [squeaks]
- WELL, THAT'S YOUR OPINION.
- [whimpers]
- [squeaking urgently]
- [squeaks]
[both squeaking]
- [squeaking urgently]
- WAIT, DID JINORA SEND
THIS SPIRIT?
IS SHE IN TROUBLE?
- [squeaks]
- [squeaking]
- [whimpering]
- JINORA'S IN TROUBLE!
WE HAVE TO GO GET HER.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW?
- BUM-JU'S FRIEND TOLD ME.
- YOU ARE ABLE TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THE SPIRITS?
- MORE OR LESS. I GET THE GIST.
LET'S GO!
- SHOULDN'T MASTER TENZIN
BE DEALING WITH THIS?
I DON'T WANT
TO GET INTO TROUBLE.
- MASTER TENZIN ISN'T HERE.
IT'S UP TO US.
IKKI AND MEELO,
GRAB SOME BISON.
AIRBENDERS, MOVE OUT!
- [squeaks]
[bison grunting]
- BISON RUSTLERS.
THEY'VE GOT KAI AND JINORA
LOCKED IN CRATES.
LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE GETTING
READY TO LEAVE. WE'LL HAVE TO
MOVE FAST.
- I DON'T KNOW IF I'M READY
TO GET IN A FIGHT
WITH SOME BISON RUSTLERS.
I CAN TELL
WITHOUT THE TELESCOPE
THAT THEY'RE MEAN-LOOKING.
- LISTEN, THIS IS WHAT
WE'VE BEEN TRAINING FOR.
- WE HAVEN'T BEEN TRAINING
THAT LONG.
- THAT'S NOT IMPORTANT NOW.
REMEMBER HOW WE PERSEVERED
TOGETHER ON THE OBSTACLE COURSE?
- YOU ACTUALLY QUIT.
- WELL, I'M NOT QUITTING NOW.
I KNOW WE'VE HAD A TOUGH TIME--
ME MORE THAN ANYONE--
BUT WE'RE AIRBENDERS,
AND THERE AREN'T MANY OF US,
SO WE'VE GOT
TO STICK TOGETHER.
THEY'VE GOT TWO OF OUR OWN
IN CAGES OUT THERE,
AND WE'RE NOT LEAVING
UNTIL WE BRING THEM HOME.
- LEAVE NO AIRBENDER BEHIND!
[bison whimpering]
- IN, DOWN, AND...
TWIST.
[bison grunts]
- FREE THE BISON FIRST.
- HEY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING OUT?
- [grunts]
- [yells]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- OOF! UGH!
[bang]
[soft music]
- [yells in slow motion]
♪ ♪
- [screams]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- [grunts]
- [groans]
- [yells]
- OOH!
[engine revs]
- KAI!
[bison bellow]
- WHAT'S GOING ON DOWN THERE?
- KAI, HELP!
- I'M COMING, JINORA.
[music intensifies]
♪ ♪
- [grunts]
[tires screech]
- [grunting]
- WHAT THE--
[bison growling]
[screams]
[grunting]
YOU GOT ME.
I GIVE UP.
[yells, grunts]
- YOU THINK
YOU CAN KIDNAP JINORA
AND ALL THESE BABY BISONS?
- [groans]
- KAI! THAT'S ENOUGH.
- AN AIRBENDER NEVER ATTACKS
A DEFENSELESS OPPONENT.
BUT THAT WAS
VERY GOOD TECHNIQUE.
[peaceful music]
♪ ♪
- MAYBE YOU BOYS
HAVEN'T HEARD,
BUT THERE'S SOME NEW AIRBENDERS
AROUND THESE PARTS.
AND YOU NEVER MESS
WITH AN AIRBENDER'S BISON.
- WITHOUT MY SHAVED HEAD,
I NEVER COULD HAVE DODGED
THAT NET.
I REALLY FELT IT
COMING AT ME.
YOU GUYS SHOULD TOTALLY
GET SHAVED.
- I'M PROUD OF YOU.
YOUR CONNECTION WITH THE SPIRITS
AND NATURAL LEADERSHIP--
YOU REMIND ME OF DAD.
- I'M SORRY I'VE BEEN
CAUSING YOU SO MUCH TROUBLE.
I GUESS I WAS JUST SCARED
OF NOT BEING ABLE
TO MEASURE UP
AS AN AIRBENDER.
YOU KNOW,
EVEN THOUGH I'M AANG'S SON,
I NEVER REALLY FELT LIKE I WAS
PART OF THE AIR NATION BEFORE.
- YOU ARE NOW.
[bison snorts]
- [laughing]
- THEY'RE SO FRIENDLY NOW.
- THE BISON ARE
THE ORIGINAL AIRBENDERS.
THEY RECOGNIZE
THEIR OWN KIND.
- I'M SORRY FOR RUNNING OFF.
- WE'RE JUST LUCKY
NO ONE WAS HURT.
- I KNOW.
- BUT I ALSO REALIZE
THAT PERHAPS I WAS
TOO HARSH WITH YOU.
- DOES THAT MEAN I CAN GET
MY AIRBENDER TATTOOS?
- IT'S HARD FOR ME TO BELIEVE
THAT MY LITTLE GIRL
HAS GROWN UP ENOUGH
TO HAVE HER TATTOOS.
BUT I PROMISE
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
FAIR ENOUGH?
- YEAH.
- JINORA, LOOK!
THEY'RE FLYING!
[bison grunting]
- I GUESS
EVERYONE IS GROWING UP.