- Tenzin: EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
Shiro: ZAHEER
INFILTRATED ZAOFU
AND ATTEMPTED TO KIDNAP
THE AVATAR.
AFTER A HARROWING BATTLE,
KORRA WAS SAVED,
BUT SHE SOON DISCOVERED
A SHOCKING TRUTH.
AIWEI, SU'S TRUSTED ADVISOR,
HAS BEEN WORKING WITH ZAHEER.
THIS TRUTH SEER TURNED TRAITOR
MANAGED TO ESCAPE,
BUT SU TASKS TEAM AVATAR
WITH TRACKING HIM DOWN.
NOW THE HUNTED
BECOMES THE HUNTER
AS KORRA SEARCHES
FOR ANSWERS.
AIWEI'S DEFINITELY BEEN
THROUGH HERE.
NICE TRACKING, GIRL.
LET'S ASK AROUND.
MAYBE SOMEONE'S SEEN HIM.
OOH, LOOK,
THEY HAVE A MOVER POSTER OF ME.
MUST BE BIG NUKTUK FANS.
YEAH.
I SHOULD GO OVER
AND SAY HELLO.
NO, THOSE ARE
WANTED POSTERS,
AND THERE'S ONE
FOR EACH OF US.
"WANTED BY HER MAJESTY,
THE EARTH QUEEN,
FOR CRIMES
AGAINST THE KINGDOM."
I'M GUESSING THIS IS BECAUSE
WE TOOK HER AIRBENDERS.
THEY WEREN'T HERS
TO KEEP.
I SWEAR, IF I EVER SEE HER PINCHY
LITTLE QUEEN FACE AGAIN,
I AM GONNA...
- UH, GUYS.
WE SHOULD GET OUT OF HERE.
- WHERE IS EVERYONE?
I'VE BEEN WAITING TO LEAVE
FOR HALF AN HOUR.
AND GOOD MORNING
TO YOU TOO, LIN.
NOW, DON'T GET MAD.
KORRA'S FINE.
I'M JUST WAITING TO HEAR
IF SHE TRACKED DOWN AIWEI YET.
WHAT?
YOU LET KORRA GO?
I THOUGHT WE WERE
ON THE SAME PAGE ABOUT THIS,
AND THEN YOU GO STAB ME
IN THE BACK?
OH, DON'T BE
SO OVERDRAMATIC.
YOU CAN'T CONTROL
THE AVATAR'S EVERY MOVE.
- I CAN TRY.
- NAGA FOUND SOMETHING.
OH, SORRY.
I FORGOT TO BRING TREATS.
BUT GOOD GIRL.
- THIS MUST BE AIWEI'S JEEP.
HE CAN'T BE FAR.
BOLIN AND I WILL INVESTIGATE
THE MISTY PALMS OASIS
AND SEE
IF HE'S HOLED UP THERE.
YES, I LOVE IT
WHEN YOU TALK LIKE A COP.
- I'M COMING TOO.
- NO.
YOU AND ASAMI WAIT HERE
IN CASE HE COMES BACK.
BESIDES, WE DON'T WANT TO CALL TOO
MUCH ATTENTION TO OURSELVES.
- ALL RIGHT.
- OOH.
MAKO, MAKO, MAKO,
WE SHOULD WEAR DISGUISES
AND PRETEND
WE'RE GOING UNDERCOVER.
THAT WAY,
NO ONE WILL RECOGNIZE US.
POLICE WORK IS SO EXCITING.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE NEED
OUR UNDERCOVER IDENTITIES.
I'M AN EX-UNITED FORCES
OPERATIVE NAMED TING-TING.
WAR WAS THE ONLY WOMAN
I EVER LOVED,
UNTIL IVY CAME ALONG
AND SHOWED ME WHAT REAL LOVE IS.
TRAGICALLY,
SHE WAS TAKEN FROM ME
BY MY ARCHENEMY DR. RAZOR,
AND HE...
ENOUGH.
LET'S JUST FIND AIWEI.
BUT I HAVEN'T EVEN TOLD YOU
YOUR BACKSTORY.
I'M A COP.
I DON'T HAVE A BACKSTORY.
- OOH, YOU'RE GOOD AT THIS.
SHOO.
HUMAN CUSTOMERS ONLY.
LET'S SEE IF THIS GUY
KNOWS ANYTHING.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR A MAN
ABOUT 60, BALDING,
WEARING GLASSES
AND A LONG GREEN ROBE.
AND HE'S GOT
THIS WEIRD PIERCING
THAT GOES FROM HIS NOSE
TO HIS EAR.
FREAKS ME OUT.
- YEAH, SURE.
SOUNDS LIKE A GUY
WHO CAME IN LAST NIGHT.
I TOLD HIM I HAD
THE BEST DRINKS IN THE EARTH KINGDOM,
AND HE CALLED ME A LIAR.
THAT'S HIM.
ANY IDEA WHERE HE IS NOW?
NO, AFRAID NOT.
BUT HE WAS RIGHT.
MY DRINKS ARE TERRIBLE.
ARE YOU OKAY?
- I'M JUST FRUSTRATED.
WHAT DOES ZAHEER
WANT WITH ME?
WHAT'S HIS PLAN?
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT I THINK I FOUND A CLUE.
"XAI BAU'S GROVE,
SUNDOWN."
THIS MUST BE WHERE AND WHEN
AIWEI'S GOING TO MEET ZAHEER.
ALL RIGHT,
XAI BAU'S GROVE,
WHERE ARE YOU?
GO AWAY.
I'M TRYING TO FIND SOMETHING.
WELL, AREN'T YOU
A CUTE LITTLE...
OW! HEY!
- NO LUCK HERE.
I THINK THERE MIGHT BE
A COUPLE BOUNTY HUNTERS
OVER THERE
WHO RECOGNIZE ME.
WE'VE BEEN MADE.
LET'S LOSE 'EM.
OKAY, I THINK WE'RE CLEAR.
WE SHOULD HEAD BACK
TO KORRA
BEFORE SOMEONE ELSE
RECOGNIZES US.
- WE COULD, OR
WE COULD FOLLOW AIWEI
INSTEAD.
LOOK.
ALL RIGHT, PLAY IT COOL.
FOLLOW MY LEAD.
TING-TING
ALWAYS FINDS HIS MAN.
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
I'LL GO GET KORRA.
WE FOUND AIWEI
HIDING IN AN INN.
THAT'S GREAT.
WE FOUND SOMETHING TOO.
IT LOOKS LIKE HE'S GOING
TO MEET ZAHEER AT SUNDOWN
AT A PLACE
CALLED XAI BAU'S GROVE,
BUT I CAN'T FIND IT ANYWHERE
ON THE MAP.
LET'S GO BUST
AIWEI'S DOOR DOWN
AND FINALLY GET SOME ANSWERS.
NO, ONCE AIWEI KNOWS
WE'RE ON TO HIM,
WE LOSE OUR ADVANTAGE.
I SAY WE STAKE OUT HIS ROOM,
AND WHEN HE LEAVES
FOR THIS MEETING,
WE FOLLOW HIM.
AND HE'LL LEAD US
STRAIGHT TO ZAHEER.
- GOOD AFTERNOON.
WE'D LIKE A ROOM
ON THE GROUND FLOOR
ACROSS FROM 102, PLEASE.
FORGET IT. LAST TIME A BUNCH OF
TEENAGERS CAME IN HERE,
THEY TRASHED THE WHOLE ROOM.
- WE FOUND YOU.
HEY, NO BENDING IN HERE.
TAKE IT OUTSIDE.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WE'RE NOT HERE TO FIGHT YOU.
WE'RE HERE TO MEET NUKTUK.
- WE'RE YOUR BIGGEST FANS.
COULD YOU MAKE IT OUT
TO LILY AND MACAO?
UH, I'D BE HAPPY TO.
ALWAYS LOVE MEETING MY FANS.
I MADE THIS NUKTUK DOLL
FOR YOU.
- AW, IT'S CUTE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
YOUR FRIEND WAS A MOVER STAR?
I'D BE HAPPY TO RENT YOU
ANY ROOM IN THE INN.
WE'LL JUST TAKE THE ONE
ACROSS FROM 102.
BUT THAT ROOM IS TOO SMALL
FOR THE FOUR OF YOU.
TRUST ME.
IT'LL BE PERFECT.
I'D JUST LIKE TO STATE
FOR THE RECORD
THAT THIS ROOM
IS NOT PERFECT.
NAGA!
- THERE HE IS.
I THOUGHT STAKEOUTS
WERE SUPPOSED TO BE EXCITING.
THIS ISN'T AT ALL.
OOH, I WONDER
IF THERE'S ANY SNACKS IN HERE.
HEY, LOOK!
A PAI SHO BOARD.
MAKO, YOU WANT TO PLAY?
- KIND OF BUSY HERE, BRO.
- I'LL PLAY.
- OH, WELL...
NO OFFENSE, BUT I LEARNED
STREET PAI SHO FROM SHADY SHIN,
AND I AM PRETTY GOOD,
SO WOULDN'T REALLY BE
A FAIR GAME.
SO? I LEARNED TO PLAY
FROM MY DAD,
THE DIABOLICAL GENIUS.
I'LL DESTROY YOU.
WELL, LOOKS LIKE
WE HAVE OURSELVES
A PAI SHO-DOWN.
LADIES FIRST.
- HMM.
I DON'T WANT TO RUSH YOU,
BUT LET'S SPEED THINGS UP A BIT.
- WHY?
THIS GAME IS ALL ABOUT SLOW,
METHODICAL STRATEGY.
NO, IT'S NOT;
THIS IS A FAST-PACED,
EDGE-OF-YOUR-SEAT
GAME OF CHANCE.
DON'T THINK.
JUST GO.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT SHADY SHIN TAUGHT YOU,
BUT IT WASN'T
THE REAL PAI SHO.
- OH, REALLY?
I THINK OUR FRIEND
MR. RULE BOOK
MIGHT DISAGREE WITH YOU.
"THE ORIGINS OF PAI SHO
DATE BACK OVER 10,000 YEARS.
IT IS A GAME OF BOTH STRATEGY
AND CHANCE."
WAIT, HOW COULD IT BE BOTH?
- LET ME SEE THAT.
"THERE HAVE BEEN
COUNTLESS VARIATIONS
"OF PAI SHO
THROUGH THE CENTURIES,
"AND EACH CULTURE
HAS ITS OWN RULES
AND VARIATIONS ON THE GAME."
- THAT'S NO HELP AT ALL.
KORRA, AS THE AVATAR,
YOU NEED TO STANDARDIZE
THESE PAI SHO RULES.
OKAY. I'LL PUT THAT
ON MY TO-DO LIST
RIGHT AFTER "BRINGING BACK
THE AIR NATION"
AND "TAKING DOWN THE GROUP
THAT TRIED TO KIDNAP ME."
THAT'S COOL.
WHENEVER YOU GET TO IT.
ASSUMING WE DO FIND ZAHEER,
WHAT THEN?
- THEN I MAKE HIM TALK.
HE WAS LOCKED AWAY
FOR 13 YEARS, KORRA,
AND NEVER BROKE.
I DON'T THINK
A LITTLE BENDING
IS GOING TO INTIMIDATE
THIS GUY.
- YOU HAVE A BETTER IDEA?
- YEAH, WE SPY ON THEM.
IF AIWEI AND ZAHEER DON'T KNOW
THEY'RE BEING WATCHED,
THEY'LL TALK FREELY.
THEN WE'LL KNOW WHO THEY ARE
AND WHAT THEY WANT.
- THAT'S JUST LIKE PAI SHO.
"IN ORDER TO DEFEAT
YOUR OPPONENT,
YOU FIRST HAVE TO KNOW
YOUR OPPONENT."
THEN I GUESS
I KNOW YOU PRETTY WELL.
I WIN.
- WHAT?
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THAT WAS JUST A FLUKE.
BEST TWO OUT OF THREE.
OH, COME ON!
BEST FOUR OUT OF SEVEN.
8 OUT OF 15.
17 OUT OF 33?
LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE ON THE ROPES THIS TIME.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
YOU MIGHT ACTUALLY WIN THIS ONE.
- NO, PABU!
WHY?
IT'S ALMOST SUNDOWN.
WHY HASN'T AIWEI LEFT YET?
MAYBE HE SLIPPED OUT
WHEN YOU WEREN'T LOOKING.
NO, I JUST SAW HIM
PEEKING OUT THE WINDOW
15 MINUTES AGO.
IT'S IN MY LOGBOOK.
- I'M GOING OVER THERE.
- KORRA, WAIT.
YOU'RE GONNA BLOW
OUR ELEMENT OF SURPRISE.
IT'S OVER, AIWEI.
WHERE'S...
WHAT?
- THAT'S A WEIRD WAY TO NAP.
- HE'S NOT SLEEPING.
HE'S MEDITATING.
WAIT.
ASAMI, THOSE SPIRITS WERE TRYING TO
TELL US SOMETHING EARLIER.
XAI BAU'S GROVE
ISN'T ON THE MAP
BECAUSE IT'S NOT
IN THE PHYSICAL WORLD.
IT'S IN THE SPIRIT WORLD.
I'M GOING IN AFTER HIM.
WE'LL WATCH HIM
IN CASE HE WAKES UP.
BE CAREFUL.
WHAT HAPPENED
BACK IN ZAOFU?
YOU TOLD ME
WE WOULDN'T HAVE ANY PROBLEMS
GETTING THE AVATAR.
BECAUSE OF YOU,
WE'VE ALL BEEN COMPROMISED.
NO, ANY EVIDENCE WAS DESTROYED
WHEN MY LIBRARY BURNED.
WHERE IS
YOUR PHYSICAL BODY NOW?
- AT THE MISTY PALMS INN.
BUT THERE IS NO NEED TO WORRY.
I WAS NOT FOLLOWED.
- YOU LEFT A LOOSE END.
I ASSURE YOU
NO ONE KNOWS ANYTHING ABOUT US.
- NO, YOU ARE THE LOOSE END.
- ZAHEER!
IT SEEMS
AIWEI WAS MISTAKEN.
HE WAS FOLLOWED.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
WE KNEW HE'D LEAD US
STRAIGHT TO YOU.
SO WHAT DID YOU DO
WITH HIM?
HE'LL BE SPENDING ETERNITY
IN THE FOG OF LOST SOULS,
WHICH JUST LEAVES
THE TWO OF US.
- DON'T MOVE, ZAHEER.
YOU'RE GONNA GIVE ME
SOME ANSWERS.
THERE'S NO NEED
FOR AGGRESSION.
NEITHER OF US
HAS OUR BENDING,
AND I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
I'LL ANSWER
WHATEVER QUESTIONS YOU HAVE.
YOU DESERVE THAT MUCH.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW?
FIRST OFF,
WHO ARE YOU PEOPLE,
AND WHY DO YOU KEEP
TRYING TO TAKE ME?
WE ARE PART
OF A SECRET SOCIETY
DEDICATED TO RESTORING FREEDOM
TO THE WORLD.
WE ARE THE RED LOTUS.
- RED LOTUS?
ARE YOU RELATED
TO THE WHITE LOTUS?
WE ARE WHAT THE WHITE LOTUS
WAS MEANT TO BE,
BUT AFTER THE
HUNDRED YEAR WAR,
THE WHITE LOTUS
LOST ITS TRUE PURPOSE.
ITS MEMBERS CAME OUT OF HIDING
AND OPENLY SERVED THE AVATAR.
THEY BECAME NOTHING
BUT GLORIFIED BODYGUARDS
WHO SERVED CORRUPT NATIONS,
SO A GREAT MAN NAMED XAI BAU
BROKE FROM THE WHITE LOTUS
AND BEGAN HIS OWN SOCIETY.
- THAT'S A GREAT STORY,
BUT IT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
WHY YOU TRIED TO TAKE ME
WHEN I WAS A KID.
- THAT WAS UNALAQ'S IDEA.
- WHAT?
MY UNCLE WAS PART
OF THE RED LOTUS?
- AVATAR KORRA.
MISTY PALMS INN.
FIND HER.
- YOU TWO GO.
I'LL STAY HERE AND MAKE SURE
ZAHEER'S BODY IS SAFE.
I MET YOUR UNCLE
WHEN I WAS A TEENAGER
AFTER WE HAD BOTH JOINED
THE RED LOTUS.
WE LEARNED ABOUT RAAVA
AND VAATU
AND HOW AVATAR WAN
FOOLISHLY SEVERED THEM,
DISRUPTING THE BALANCE
OF THE WORLD FOREVER.
- AVATAR WAN WASN'T FOOLISH.
HE WAS TRYING
TO RESTORE BALANCE.
HE CLOSED THE PORTALS,
SEVERING HUMANS FROM SPIRITS.
EVEN YOU REALIZE
THE ERROR IN HIS WAYS.
SO ALL ALONG,
YOU AND MY UNCLE PLANNED TO USE ME
TO OPEN THE PORTALS
AND RELEASE VAATU?
THAT'S WHY YOU
TRIED TO TAKE ME WHEN I WAS A KID?
YES, AND WITH MEMBERS
OF THE RED LOTUS
AS YOUR ELEMENTAL MASTERS,
WE COULD'VE TAUGHT YOU
SO MUCH.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU WANTED
TO BRAINWASH ME
SO I'D DO
WHATEVER YOU WANTED.
- NO, KORRA.
ALL I WANTED
WAS TO SHOW THE AVATAR
A BETTER PATH
FOR THE WORLD.
- UH, I DON'T KNOW HOW,
BUT WATER ARM LADY
AND LAVA GUY FOUND US.
HOW?
I JUST SAID
I DON'T KNOW HOW.
KORRA, COME ON,
WAKE UP.
- WHAT DO WE DO?
- GET KORRA OUT OF HERE.
BOLIN AND I
WILL HOLD THEM OFF.
- THE AVATAR.
IF MY UNCLE CAME UP
WITH A PLAN
TO ABDUCT ME
WHEN I WAS A KID,
WHY WASN'T HE CAUGHT?
HE WASN'T WITH US
THAT NIGHT,
AND HE COVERED UP
HIS INVOLVEMENT AFTERWARDS.
SO HE BETRAYED YOU
JUST LIKE HE BETRAYED ME.
YES, HE ALLOWED ME
AND MY FRIENDS
TO REMAIN IMPRISONED
WHILE HE PURSUED
HIS OWN SELFISH GOALS.
UNALAQ BECOMING A DARK AVATAR
WAS NEVER PART OF OUR MISSION.
AND WHAT IS YOUR MISSION
EXACTLY?
- I WANT WHAT YOU WANT,
TO RESTORE BALANCE
TO THIS WORLD.
I DON'T THINK OUR IDEAS
OF BALANCE ARE THE SAME.
- ARE YOU SURE ABOUT THAT?
YOU KEPT
THE SPIRIT PORTALS OPEN,
BUT WHY STOP THERE?
BRINGING THE SPIRITS BACK
SHOULD ONLY BE THE BEGINNING.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THE IDEA OF HAVING NATIONS
AND GOVERNMENTS
IS AS FOOLISH
AS KEEPING
THE HUMAN
AND SPIRIT REALMS SEPARATE.
YOU'VE HAD TO DEAL
WITH A MORONIC PRESIDENT
AND A TYRANNICAL QUEEN.
DON'T YOU THINK THE WORLD
WOULD BE BETTER OFF
IF LEADERS LIKE THEM
WERE ELIMINATED?
- NO.
I MEAN, I DON'T REALLY AGREE
WITH WHAT THEY'VE DONE,
BUT TAKING OUT WORLD LEADERS
ISN'T THE ANSWER.
IT WASN'T TOO LONG AGO
THAT THE AIRBENDERS
WERE NEARLY ALL WIPED OUT
THANKS TO THE FIRE LORD'S DESIRE
FOR WORLD DOMINANCE.
TRUE FREEDOM
CAN ONLY BE ACHIEVED
WHEN OPPRESSIVE GOVERNMENTS
ARE TORN DOWN.
BUT THAT WON'T
BRING BALANCE.
IT WILL THROW THE WORLD
INTO CHAOS.
- EXACTLY.
THE NATURAL ORDER
IS DISORDER.
DO YOU KNOW WHO ONCE SAID,
"NEW GROWTH CANNOT EXIST
WITHOUT FIRST
THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE OLD"?
- NO.
THE WISE GURU LAGHIMA,
AN AIRBENDER.
I CAN'T BEAT THIS GUY.
IT'S LIKE
I'M GIVING HIM AMMO.
WANT TO TRADE?
- GO GET THE AVATAR.
I HAVE THESE TWO
UNDER CONTROL.
YOU KNOW, BEING LOCKED AWAY
FOR SO MANY YEARS,
I WAS BEGINNING
TO LOSE HOPE,
BUT WHEN I AWOKE
WITH AIRBENDING,
I KNEW I WOULD BE THE ONE
TO DESTROY THE OLD WORLD
AND PLANT SEEDS
FOR A NEW WORLD TO FLOURISH.
ZAHEER, PLEASE,
AS AN AIRBENDER,
YOU COULD HELP MAKE A POSITIVE
DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD
INSTEAD OF DESTROYING IT.
YOU'RE A VERY SMART
YOUNG WOMAN, KORRA,
BUT YOU MUST REALIZE
THAT ONCE CHANGE BEGINS,
IT CANNOT BE STOPPED,
EVEN BY THE AVATAR.
ENOUGH WITH
YOUR PHILOSOPHICAL MUMBO JUMBO.
I WANT TO KNOW ONE THING:
IF YOU DO CAPTURE ME,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO WITH ME?
YOU'LL HAVE THAT ANSWER
SOON ENOUGH.
THE RED LOTUS
SHOULD HAVE YOU BY NOW.
SEE YOU
IN THE PHYSICAL WORLD.
- ZAHEER!
ZAHEER, YOU TRICKED ME.
LET ME GO!
ASAMI, ARE YOU OKAY?
WHERE'S THE REST
OF THE RED LOTUS?
- WHAT'S THE RED LOTUS?
AND ZAHEER DIDN'T CAPTURE US.
THE EARTH QUEEN'S FORCES DID.
- WHERE ARE WE?
- I'M NOT SURE.
SOME CAMP BY THE DESERT.
THEY'RE TAKING US BACK
TO BA SING SE.
THE EARTH QUEEN'S ARMY
SNATCHED UP THE AVATAR
BEFORE I COULD.
BUT WE FIGURED
YOU COULD FIND A USE FOR THESE TWO.
LOAD THEM
IN THE TRUCK.
WE'RE TAKING A TRIP
TO BA SING SE.