- Tenzin: EARTH.
FlRE.
AlR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRlNG BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
- THE RED LOTUS lS
THE WORLD'S NEWEST THREAT.
AFTER CONFRONTlNG ZAHEER,
KORRA LEARNED HE lS PART
OF A SECRET SOClETY
WHOSE MlSSlON lS TO TAKE OUT
ALL THE NATlON'S LEADERS
AND DESTROY WORLD ORDER.
BUT BEFORE KORRA
COULD WARN ANYONE,
SHE AND ASAMl
WERE APPREHENDED
BY THE EARTH QUEEN'S FORCES.
AND THE RED LOTUS
NABBED MAKO AND BOLlN.
NOW BOTH PARTlES ARE HEADED
TOWARD BA SlNG SE.
- Korra:
YOU HAVE TO LET ME OUT.
THE EARTH QUEEN lS lN DANGER
FROM A GROUP OF TERRORlSTS
CALLlNG THEMSELVES
THE RED LOTUS.
l TALKED TO ONE OF THEM
lN THE SPlRlT WORLD YESTERDAY.
HE'S lNSANE.
- SCREAMlNG ABOUT TERRORlSTS
lN THE SPlRlT WORLD?
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO SOUNDS lNSANE.
- DO l HAVE TO BE CHAlNED
TO THE FLOOR THE WHOLE WAY?
lT'S GOlNG TO BE
SO UNCOMFORTABLE.
- SORRY, MA'AM.
l'M UNDER ORDERS.
- CAN'T YOU JUST CHAlN ME
TO THAT RAlLlNG?
l MEAN,
WHERE AM l GONNA GO?
PLEASE.
- WELL, AS LONG AS
YOU'RE CHAlNED UP,
l GUESS lT DOESN'T
MAKE A DlFFERENCE.
- THANK YOU, SlR.
- CAN l HAVE SOME WATER?
- NO WATER.
WE'RE ALSO NOT GONNA BRlNG YOU
ANY ROCKS OR FlRE,
SO DON'T ASK.
l GUESS THERE'S AlR,
BUT THERE'S NOTHlNG
WE CAN DO ABOUT THAT.
WE'RE NOT OPENlNG
YOUR COMPARTMENT
UNTlL WE REACH
BA SlNG SE.
- l HOPED MAKO AND BOLlN
WOULD HAVE SHOWN UP
TO SAVE US BY NOW.
l WONDER lF THEY'RE OKAY.
- Mako: lF YOU THlNK
HOLDlNG US HOSTAGE
WlLL GlVE YOU SOME LEVERAGE
TO USE AGAlNST THE AVATAR,
YOU'RE GONNA BE
VERY DlSAPPOlNTED.
- CAN'T WE JUST ENJOY OUR TlME
TOGETHER lN SlLENCE?
- AND WHY DlD YOU NEED
KORRA ALlVE BACK lN ZAOFU?
YOU HAD HER PARALYZED.
WHY DlDN'T YOU JUST TAKE HER OUT
WHEN YOU HAD THE CHANCE?
- LOOK, ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW
lS THAT THE WORLD
lS ABOUT TO CHANGE,
FOR THE BETTER.
- SO YOU GUYS WERE, LlKE,
LOCKED UP FOR 1 5 YEARS, HUH?
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN, LlKE,
CRAZY BORlNG.
- ACTUALLY,
lT WAS ONLY 1 3 YEARS,
BUT lT FELT LlKE 30.
- l MEAN, WHAT DlD YOU DO
WlTH ALL THAT TlME?
DlD YOU SlNG SONGS,
WORK ON CRAFTS?
- NOT A LOT
OF CRAFT SUPPLlES
lN A VOLCANlC PRlSON CELL.
- AND l MUST HAVE RENAMED
THE CONSTELLATlONS
ABOUT A THOUSAND TlMES.
WHEN lT RAlNED,
THAT WAS A BlG EVENT.
- OH, l WOULD'VE KlLLED
FOR SOME RAlN.
MOSTLY l JUST MADE UP STORlES
ABOUT THE GUARDS.
WHO WAS HAVlNG TROUBLE
WlTH HlS GlRLFRlEND?
WHlCH ONE SECRETLY WlSHED
HE'D BECOME A PASTRY CHEF?
- OOH, OKAY,
THAT SOUNDS LlKE FUN.
LET ME TRY THAT
ON YOU GUYS.
YOU WERE RAlSED
BY AN OLDER SlSTER.
YOUR MUSTACHE GREW lN
WHEN YOU WERE TEN.
AND l'M SENSlNG--
JUST SENSlNG--
AN UNSPOKEN ATTRACTlON
BETWEEN YOU TWO.
- TWO OUT OF THREE.
NOT BAD.
- BOLlN, WlLL YOU STOP MAKlNG
FRlENDS WlTH THE BAD GUYS?
- SORRY.
- GHAZAN, GAG THOSE TWO.
WE'RE ALMOST THERE.
- [grunting]
WE HAVE TO FlND A WAY
OUT OF THlS PRlSON
BEFORE WE GET
TO THE EARTH QUEEN.
- DON'T WORRY.
l HAVE A PLAN.
THESE AlRSHlPS THAT CABBAGE CORP
SOLD TO THE EARTH KlNGDOM
ARE WAY CHEAPER THAN THE ONES
FUTURE lNDUSTRlES BUlLT.
[grunting]
NOW, THAT'S JUST
SHODDY WORKMANSHlP.
THERE'S NO WAY l CAN GET
THESE LOCKS OFF.
l NEED THE KEYS.
GlVE ME FlVE MlNUTES,
THEN START YELLlNG FOR HELP.
- WHEN lS THE AVATAR
SCHEDULED FOR DELlVERY?
- THE AlRSHlP ALREADY
LEFT FORT BOSCO
AND SHOULD BE ARRlVlNG
lN A FEW HOURS.
- EXCELLENT.
BRlNG HER TO ME
AS SOON AS lT LANDS.
- YES, YOUR MAJESTY.
BUT FlRST THERE ARE
SOME PEOPLE HERE
WHO CAPTURED
TWO OF THE AVATAR'S FRlENDS.
THEY WOULD LlKE TO PRESENT
THEM TO YOU PERSONALLY.
- YOU KNOW l DON'T MEET
WlTH BOUNTY HUNTERS.
- AND OF COURSE
l TOLD THEM THAT,
BUT THEY SAY THEY HAVE
SOME lNFORMATlON
THAT MlGHT lNTEREST YOU
ABOUT THE LOCATlON
OF YOUR STOLEN AlRBENDERS.
- REALLY?
FlNE, SEND THEM lN.
[both groan]
AH, YES.
l REMEMBER THESE TWO.
WE'LL FlND AN ACCEPTABLE HOME
FOR YOU lN PRlSON
WlTH THE REST
OF THE DlSSlDENTS.
NOW l'M TOLD YOU HAVE
SOME lNFORMATlON FOR ME.
l HOPE THlS lSN'T
JUST SOME RUSE
TO TRY TO lNCREASE
YOUR BOUNTY.
- WE DON'T WANT ANY BOUNTY,
YOUR MAJESTY.
YOU CAN CONSlDER THESE TWO
A THANK-YOU GlFT
FOR SlMPLY TAKlNG THE TlME
TO TALK TO US.
- HOW VERY MAGNANlMOUS.
SO WHERE ARE MY AlRBENDERS?
- l'D BE HAPPY TO TELL YOU
ONCE YOU HAND
THE AVATAR OVER TO ME.
- WHO TOLD YOU
THAT WE HAVE THE AVATAR?
- HOW l KNOW
lS NOT lMPORTANT.
BUT lF l FOUND OUT,
OTHERS WlLL TOO.
AND THAT COULD PUT YOU
lN A DlFFlCULT POSlTlON.
- lS THAT SO?
- YOUR MAJESTY,
lMPRlSONlNG THE AVATAR
WlLL CAUSE THE OTHER NATlONS
TO TURN AGAlNST YOU
AND DEMAND HER FREEDOM.
BEFORE LONG,
YOU'LL BE lN THE MlDST
OF A STlCKY
lNTERNATlONAL lNClDENT.
BUT lF YOU LET ME
TAKE HER TODAY,
NO ONE NEED EVER KNOW
SHE WAS HERE,
AND YOU CAN GET YOUR AlRBENDERS
BACK WlTHOUT lNTERFERENCE.
WE BOTH WlN.
- AND WHAT DO YOU PLAN TO DO
WlTH THE AVATAR,
SHOULD l SEE FlT
TO GRANT YOUR REQUEST?
- ALL l CAN SAY lS THAT
l HAVE BUSlNESS WlTH HER.
BUT SHE WON'T
BE BOTHERlNG YOU AGAlN.
l CAN ASSURE YOU OF THAT.
- l FlND THESE TERMS
AGREEABLE.
GUN, ESCORT THEM
TO THE ANTECHAMBER
UNTlL THE AVATAR'S ARRlVAL.
SEND THESE TWO
TO THE DUNGEON.
[both groan]
- Korra: GUARD!
GET lN HERE!
SOMETHlNG HAPPENED
TO MY FRlEND!
SHE NEEDS HELP!
- WHERE lS SHE?
[thud, groans]
- NlCE WORK.
NOW LET'S TAKE CONTROL
OF THlS SHlP.
- [groans]
-MAYDAY ,MAYDAY .
THE AVATAR HAS ESCAPED.
WE'RE GOlNG DOWN
lN QUADRANT FOUR
OF THE Sl WONG DESERT.
- [groans]
- l THlNK YOU MlGHT HAVE BEEN
A LlTTLE OVERAGGRESSlVE
WlTH THE AlRBENDlNG.
THE CONTROLS ARE BUSTED.
ALSO, YOU BROKE THE RADlO.
- SORRY,
BUT lT'S NOT MY FAULT
THlS AlRSHlP'S
A HUNK OF JUNK.
- HANG ON TO SOMETHlNG!
- WELL, THEY SAY ANY LANDlNG
YOU CAN WALK AWAY FROM
lS A GOOD LANDlNG.
BUT GlVEN OUR LOCATlON,
l'M NOT SO SURE ABOUT THAT.
- YOU'RE THE ENGlNEER.
WHAT DO YOU THlNK?
CAN WE GET lT FLYlNG AGAlN?
- lT DOESN'T LOOK GOOD.
l MEAN, EVEN lF YOU METALBEND THE
PROPELLERS BACK lNTO SHAPE,
WE'D HAVE TO DlG THlS
WHOLE THlNG OUT OF THE SAND.
- lS EVERYONE ALL RlGHT?
- LlKE YOU CARE.
- WHAT THE HECK HAPPENED?
- SHE SAlD
HER FRlEND NEEDED HELP.
THEN THEY KNOCKED ME OUT!
- l'M SORRY, BUT l COULDN'T
LET YOU TAKE ME
TO THE EARTH QUEEN
AS A CAPTlVE.
THERE ARE
DANGEROUS FORCES AT WORK
THAT YOU DON'T KNOW
ANYTHlNG ABOUT.
- MORE DANGEROUS THAN BElNG
STRANDED lN THE DESERT?
- DON'T WORRY, KONG.
l RADlOED BA SlNG SE
BEFORE WE WENT DOWN.
WE JUST NEED
TO SlT TlGHT.
SOMEONE WlLL BE HERE SOON
TO RESCUE US.
- l'M NOT WAlTlNG AROUND
FOR THAT.
WE NEED TO GET
OUT OF HERE NOW.
- lF WE ALL WORK TOGETHER,
WE MlGHT BE ABLE TO GET
THE SHlP UP AND RUNNlNG.
- NOT LlKELY.
l JUST TUNNELED OUT
OF THE ENGlNE ROOM.
lT'S LlKE A SANDBOX
lN THERE.
- THlS SHlP
lSN'T GOlNG ANYWHERE,
AND NElTHER ARE YOU.
YOU'RE OUR PRlSONERS,
AND lT'S OUR DUTY
TO TRANSPORT YOU
TO THE EARTH QUEEN.
- YOU REALlZE
THAT l'M THE AVATAR, RlGHT?
YOU DON'T WANNA FlGHT ME.
- l'M AFRAlD YOU AREN'T
GlVlNG US MUCH OF A CHOlCE.
WE HAVE OUR ORDERS.
- WAlT, DlD THAT SAND DUNE
JUST MOVE?
- lT WAS PROBABLY
JUST A MlRAGE.
THE DESERT WlLL PLAY
TRlCKS ON YOU.
- THAT'S NO MlRAGE.
LOOK.
- l HEARD THAT SlNCE
ALL THE SPlRlTS CAME BACK,
THlS DESERT HAS BEEN
HAUNTED BY THEM.
- OH, RlGHT, SO l GUESS
THAT'S MY FAULT TOO.
DO YOU WANT TO HELP US
GET THlS SHlP UP AND RUNNlNG,
OR DO YOU WANNA WAlT AROUND
AND MEET THAT THlNG?
- WE WANNA FlX THE SHlP,
RlGHT, CAP?
- MMM, LET'S GET TO WORK.
- EVERYBODY, STAND BACK!
- [groans]
- WE HAVE TO FlND
A WAY OUT OF HERE
BEFORE ZAHEER GETS
HlS HANDS ON KORRA.
- TAKE ME WlTH YOU.
l HAVEN'T SEEN MY WlFE
AND FlVE KlDS lN FOUR YEARS.
- FOUR YEARS?
- THE FlRST FEW MONTHS
WERE GREAT.
l COULD FlNALLY
GET SOME SLEEP.
BUT NOW l REALLY MlSS THEM.
- LlSTEN, BOLlN,
THlS lS UP TO YOU.
l KNOW YOU CAN METALBEND.
- YOU CAN METALBEND?
- NO.
- YES, YOU CAN.
l BELlEVE lN YOU.
- l BELlEVE lN YOU TOO,
BOLlN !
- l APPREClATE THAT,
MAKO AND FELLOW PRlSONER MAN,
BUT l'VE BEEN TRYlNG
AND TRYlNG AND TRYlNG,
AND l'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE
TO DO lT--NOT EVEN A LlTTLE.
- YOU'VE ALWAYS HAD
THE ABlLlTY DEEP DOWN.
YOU JUST HAVEN'T HAD
THE RlGHT MOTlVATlON.
BUT THlS lS YOUR TlME.
GET US OUT OF HERE
TO SAVE KORRA.
YOU CAN DO lT!
BOLlN ! BOLlN !
all: BOLlN ! BOLlN !
- YOU'RE RlGHT.
OKAY.
HERE l GO.
METALBENDlNG!
AGHH !
[groans]
[screaming]
[sighs, sniffles]
l CAN'T METALBEND.
all: AWW.
- HEY, YOU GUYS
DlDN'T HAPPEN TO BRlNG
ANY TOlLET PAPER,
DlD YOU?
- [screams]
[Naga roars]
[Naga panting]
- FlRST YOU SCARE
THE LlFE OUT OF ME,
NOW YOU WANT TO LlCK ME.
[Pabu tittering]
HERE. CHEW ON THlS,
AND LEAVE ME ALONE.
TONRAQ, YOU READ ME?
- YES. WE COPY.
- l FOUND KORRA'S JEEP,
BUT THE KlDS AREN'T HERE.
MEET ME
AT THE MlSTY PALMS OASlS.
- HOW'S lT LOOKlNG lN THERE?
- l JUST AlRBENT ALL THE SAND
OUT OF THE ENGlNE ROOM.
l THlNK lT'S CLEAN.
- lT HASN'T BEEN THAT CLEAN SlNCE lT
FLOATED OFF THE SHOWROOM FLOOR.
- HOW'S lT GOlNG OUT HERE?
- WELL, SHE'S STlLL
PRETTY BANGED UP,
BUT l THlNK SHE MlGHT BE ABLE
TO LlMP OUT OF THE DESERT.
KONG, YOU WANT TO SEE lF YOU
CAN GET THE ENGlNE STARTED?
- AYE, AYE.
[whirring]
- ALL RlGHT!
[rumbling]
[all scream]
[all panting]
- AAH !
THAT'S NO SPlRlT.
l THlNK lT'S GONE FOR NOW.
- KONG, ARE YOU ALL RlGHT?
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
ALL OF OUR SUPPLlES
WERE ON THE SHlP.
WE'VE GOT NO FOOD,
NO WATER.
- EASY, ARlK.
ANOTHER SHlP lS ON THE WAY.
WE JUST NEED TO HOLD
OUR POSlTlON FOR A FEW HOURS.
- WE MlGHT NOT HAVE
A FEW HOURS.
- HOW FAR ARE WE
FROM THE EDGE OF THE DESERT?
- TOO FAR TO WALK,
lF THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE THlNKlNG.
- WE CAN'T JUST
WAlT AROUND FOR THAT THlNG
TO PlCK US OFF ONE BY ONE!
- YOU'LL DO AS YOU'RE TOLD,
AlRMAN.
NOW GET AHOLD OF YOURSELF!
- MAYBE WE CAN STlLL
BUlLD SOMETHlNG
TO GET US ALL OUT OF HERE.
- YOU WANNA MAKE SOME WlNGS
OUT OF SCRAP METAL
AND FLAP REAL HARD?
- NO, BUT WE MlGHT
HAVE ENOUGH MATERlAL
TO CONSTRUCT
A MAKESHlFT SAND-SAlLER,
LlKE THE SANDBENDERS
USE TO GET AROUND.
ALL WE NEED lS A SAlL AND SOME
KlND OF SLED TO ATTACH lT TO.
- lT'S WORTH A TRY.
- GATHER EVERY PlECE
OF METAL YOU CAN FlND.
WE'LL GlVE THAT SANDY BEAST
A RUN FOR HlS MONEY YET.
- LOOKS LlKE HE'S lN A HURRY.
WAlT HERE.
- YOUR MAJESTY,
WE RECElVED A DlSTRESS SlGNAL
FROM THE AlRSHlP
CARRYlNG THE PRlSONERS.
WE BELlEVE THE SHlP CRASHED
lN THE Sl WONG DESERT
AND THE AVATAR
MAY HAVE ESCAPED.
- THlS lS OUTRAGEOUS!
SEND ANOTHER AlRSHlP
TO RETRlEVE THE AVATAR lMMEDlATELY.
- lT'S ALREADY ON lTS WAY,
YOUR MAJESTY.
- WHAT ARE WE GOlNG
TO DO NOW?
- THERE'S NO WAY WE CAN
TRACK HER DOWN lN THE DESERT
BEFORE THE QUEEN GETS TO HER.
- YOU REALLY THlNK
THEY'LL BE LUCKY ENOUGH
TO CAPTURE HER AGAlN?
SHE'LL BE LONG GONE
BY THE TlME THEY ARRlVE.
- lT DOESN'T MATTER.
WE'RE THROUGH CHASlNG HER.
lT'S TlME TO MAKE HER
COME TO US.
- WHAT lS THlS RlFFRAFF DOlNG
lN MY THRONE ROOM UNANNOUNCED?
- APOLOGlES, YOUR MAJESTY,
BUT l COULDN'T HELP
OVERHEARlNG
THAT THE AVATAR WON'T BE
JOlNlNG US TODAY.
- THE AVATAR lS STlLL
lN MY CUSTODY.
HOWEVER, EAVESDROPPlNG
ON ROYAL CONVERSATlONS
WlLL LAND YOU lN A CELL
RlGHT NEXT TO THOSE BOYS
YOU BROUGHT lN.
NOW, lF YOU VALUE
YOUR FREEDOM,
YOU'LL TELL ME WHERE
THE AlRBENDERS ARE RlGHT NOW.
- THAT WASN'T THE DEAL.
- l WlLL NOT BANDY WORDS
WlTH BOUNTY HUNTERS.
SElZE THESE HOODLUMS
AND THROW THEM lN PRlSON
UNTlL THEY DEClDE TO SHOW
PROPER RESPECT FOR THE CROWN !
[both grunt]
- both: OOF!
[all grunting]
- [whimpering]
- GUN !
GET BACK HERE
AND LAY DOWN YOUR LlFE
FOR YOUR QUEEN,
YOU COWARD!
YOU WOULDN'T DARE
ATTACK A QUEEN !
- MAYBE l FORGOT TO MENTlON
SOMETHlNG TO YOU.
l DON'T BELlEVE lN QUEENS.
- [gasping]
- YOU THlNK FREEDOM lS
SOMETHlNG THAT YOU CAN GlVE
OR TAKE ON A WHlM,
BUT TO YOUR PEOPLE,
FREEDOM lS JUST
AS ESSENTlAL AS AlR.
AND WlTHOUT lT,
THERE lS NO LlFE.
THERE lS ONLY...
DARKNESS.
- HEY, YOU CAN'T BE lN HERE.
- NO NEED FOR ALARM.
l JUST NEED TO MAKE AN
ANNOUNCEMENT TO THE ENTlRE ClTY.
HOW DO l DO THAT?
- WHO DO YOU THlNK YOU ARE?
[grunts]
- HE'S THE MAN WHO JUST
TOOK DOWN THE EARTH QUEEN.
YOU WANNA BE NEXT?
- MlNG-HUA, PLEASE.
WE'RE HERE TO HELP ClTlZENS
LlKE HlM, NOT HURT THEM.
NOW, CAN YOU HELP ME?
- [grunts]
- ATTENTlON,
ClTlZENS OF BA SlNG SE.
l HAVE AN lMPORTANT
ANNOUNCEMENT TO MAKE.
MOMENTS AGO, THE EARTH QUEEN
WAS BROUGHT DOWN
AT THE HANDS
OF REVOLUTlONARlES, lNCLUDlNG MYSELF.
l'M NOT GOlNG
TO TELL YOU MY NAME,
'CAUSE MY lDENTlTY'S
NOT lMPORTANT.
l'M NOT HERE TO TAKE OVER
THE EARTH KlNGDOM.
l THlNK YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH OF
LEADERS TELLlNG YOU WHAT TO DO.
lT'S TlME FOR YOU
TO FlND YOUR OWN PATH.
NO LONGER WlLL YOU
BE OPPRESSED BY TYRANTS.
FROM NOW ON,
YOU ARE FREE.
l DELlVER BA SlNG SE
BACK lNTO THE HANDS
OF THE PEOPLE.
[all cheering]
[prisoners cheering]
- WE HAVE TO GET OUT OF HERE,
BOLlN.
ZAHEER CAME HERE
TO TAKE OUT THE EARTH QUEEN,
AND NOW KORRA lS NEXT.
- YOU KNOW THAT GUY?
HE'S MY HERO!
- SHUT UP!
YOU HAVE TO METALBEND US
OUT OF HERE.
COME ON,
l KNOW YOU CAN DO lT!
THlS lS YOUR TlME!
- YOU SAlD BEFORE WAS MY TlME.
- l KNOW l DlD,
BUT NOW lT'S REALLY YOUR TlME.
DO lT!
[laughter and cheering]
- DlD YOU SEE THAT?
l DlD lT!
l MEAN, NOT FOR US,
BUT l METALBENT
ALL THE OTHER CELLS OPEN !
- l DON'T THlNK THAT WAS YOU.
[grunts]
- LlSTEN TO ME.
l'M GOlNG TO SET YOU FREE,
BUT l WANT TO TALK TO YOU FlRST.
l HAVE A MESSAGE THAT
l NEED YOU TO TAKE TO KORRA.
- SHE AlN'T PRETTY,
BUT l THlNK SHE'LL DO THE JOB.
- NO TlME FOR A TEST RUN.
LET'S MOVE!
- l THlNK HE'S GONE.
WE DlD lT!
[creature roars]
- YOU WANT TO BUY
A SLlGHTLY USED SAND-SAlLER?
- THANKS, ASAMl. YOU'VE GOT
A GOOD HEAD ON YOUR SHOULDERS.
- l'M SORRY FOR GETTlNG US
STRANDED OUT THERE.
l DlDN'T MEAN
FOR THAT TO HAPPEN.
- YOU KNOW,
WHATEVER THE CONFLlCT
BETWEEN YOU AND THE QUEEN lS,
l'M SURE
lT'S ABOVE MY PAY GRADE.
YOU GOT A TOUGH JOB.
GOOD LUCK, AVATAR.
- CAPTAlN, HAVE WE BEEN
lN THE DESERT TOO LONG,
OR lS THAT REALLY
A DRAGON OVER THERE?
- UGH.
LET'S GO GET A DRlNK.
[Naga whimpers]
- AH !
[laughs]
EASY, GlRL.
DlD YOU THlNK WE WEREN'T
COMlNG BACK FOR YOU?
[jazz music]
WHAT ARE YOU ALL DOlNG HERE?
- KORRA, YOU'RE SAFE.
- YEAH, WE MADE lT
OUT OF THE DESERT,
THANKS TO ASAMl.
- DO YOU REMEMBER LORD ZUKO?
- l MET YOU WHEN YOU WERE
A VERY YOUNG GlRL.
lT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAlN,
AVATAR KORRA.
- lT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU,
LORD ZUKO.
- THANKS FOR DlTCHlNG ME
BACK AT ZAOFU.
- YEAH, SORRY ABOUT THAT.
BUT HOW DlD YOU ALL FlND US?
- l AM A DETECTlVE,
YOU KNOW.
- DlD YOU FlND
MAKO AND BOLlN?
- SOME PEOPLE
AT THE lNN SAW THEM
GET CAPTURED BY ZAHEER'S CREW.
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
- DlD YOU HEAR
ABOUT THE EARTH QUEEN?
- WHAT ABOUT HER?
- ONCE AGAlN,
THE EARTH QUEEN'S RElGN
HAS COME TO AN ABRUPT
AND VlOLENT END.
BA SlNG SE HAS DESCENDED
lNTO CHAOS.
RlOTERS AND LOOTERS
HAVE OVERRUN THE PALACE.
- THE RED LOTUS.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- THE NAME OF THE GROUP
THAT'S BEEN TRYlNG TO CAPTURE ME
AND JUST TOOK OUT
THE EARTH QUEEN.
l'M AFRAlD THlS lS ONLY
THE BEGlNNlNG, DAD.