- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- BA SING SE HAS FALLEN!
AFTER ZAHEER AND THE RED LOTUS
TOPPLED THE EARTH QUEEN,
THE CITY DESCENDED INTO CHAOS.
MEANWHILE, KORRA AND ASAMI
TRIED TO ESCAPE THEIR CAPTORS
BUT CRASHED IN THE DESERT.
AFTER GETTING TO SAFETY,
THEY MET UP
WITH LORD ZUKO, TONRAQ,
AND BEIFONG.
BACK IN BA SING SE,
ZAHEER FREED MAKO AND BOLIN,
GIVING THEM A VITAL MESSAGE
TO DELIVER TO KORRA.
BUT WILL THE BROTHERS
FIND HER IN TIME?
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
THE UPPER RING IS IN CHAOS.
- DON'T TRY TO STOP US.
WE'RE TAKING BACK WHAT'S OURS.
- STOP YOU?
I'M GONNA JOIN YOU.
I KNOW WHERE THE GOOD STUFF IS.
- SHOULD WE DO SOMETHING?
- THIS ISN'T OUR BATTLE.
WE HAVE TO DELIVER ZAHEER'S
MESSAGE TO KORRA IMMEDIATELY.
- RIGHT. OKAY.
FIND KORRA, DELIVER MESSAGE.
YEAH, THIS SHOULD BE EASY.
WE JUST GOTTA GET
OUT OF THE CITY
AND GET TO THE DESERT,
THEN SOMEHOW FIND HER
IN THE VAST, EXPANSIVE WASTELAND
THAT GOES ON FOR THOUSANDS
AND THOUSANDS OF MILES.
[sighs]
THIS ISN'T GONNA BE EASY.
- WE NEED AN AIRSHIP.
- OOH!
- EXCUSE ME, MAY I HAVE
YOUR ATTENTION PLEASE?
I'M WITH
THE REPUBLIC CITY POLICE,
AND I NEED TO COMMANDEER
THIS AIRSHIP TO HELP THE AVATAR.
- LET ME GIVE IT A SHOT.
HEY, THE QUEEN'S GOLD IS ON
THE THIRD FLOOR OF THE PALACE!
SECOND DOOR ON THE RIGHT!
YOU JUST GOTTA KNOW
HOW TO TALK TO THEM, BRO.
- THEY TOOK EVERYTHING.
I MEAN, WHO RIPS OUT
A TRANSMISSION RADIO?
- SOME FOLKS JUST
DO NOT HAVE RESPECT
FOR OTHER PEOPLE'S PROPERTY.
NOW LET'S STEAL THIS AIRSHIP!
- YOU KNOW HOW
TO FLY THIS THING?
- TECHNICALLY SPEAKING?
NO.
BUT, COME ON,
HOW HARD CAN IT BE?
[all scream]
- UP! UP!
- I DON'T SEE ANY "UP" BUTTON.
I SEE LEVERS AND SWITCHES.
OH, THERE IT IS.
- THE WHOLE CITY
IS FALLING TO PIECES.
- MAKO, OUR FAMILY'S DOWN THERE.
- MOVE OVER.
- AHH!
- WE'RE GETTING THEM OUT.
- OH, YOU THINK
JUST BECAUSE YOU DATED ASAMI,
YOU KNOW HOW TO FLY THIS
BETTER THAN ME?
- YEAH.
- BOLIN?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I CAME TO GET YOU GUYS OUT.
THIS WHOLE BLOCK
IS ABOUT TO GO UP IN FLAMES.
COME ON, MAKO AND I
HAVE AN AIRSHIP ON THE ROOF.
- WE CAN'T.
GRANDMA WON'T GO.
- THIS PLACE IS MY WHOLE WORLD.
I WILL NOT LEAVE.
OH, BUT I'M SO GLAD MY LITTLE
BOLIN HAS COME BACK TO VISIT.
SIT DOWN.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOME TEA?
- GRANDMA, WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR TEA.
- MOM, PLEASE.
- NO!
I CAN'T ABANDON THE PLACE
WHERE I RAISED MY FAMILY.
IT'S MY HOME.
- GRANDMA, THERE'S ONE THING
THAT MAKO AND I HAVE LEARNED
FROM ALL OUR YEARS
ON THE STREET:
IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHERE YOU GO.
IF YOU HAVE YOUR FAMILY
WITH YOU,
YOU'LL ALWAYS BE AT HOME.
- I'M NOT GOING.
- FINE!
YOU LEAVE ME NO CHOICE.
WE'RE ROLLING OUT!
- [gasps] WAIT.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
- THANKS FOR GETTING US
OUT OF THERE.
I MEAN, I PROBABLY COULD HAVE
HANDLED IT MYSELF
IF YOU GUYS DIDN'T SHOW UP,
BUT THANKS.
- [kisses]
MAY SHE REST IN PEACE.
THIS AIRSHIP IS NICE.
IS IT OUR NEW HOME?
- NO, GRANDMA, I'M NOT SURE
WHERE WE'RE GONNA TAKE YOU.
BUT RIGHT NOW,
WE NEED TO FIND KORRA.
- DID SOMETHING HAPPEN
TO THE AVATAR?
- I'M AFRAID SO.
HER AIRSHIP WENT DOWN
SOMEWHERE IN THE DESERT.
SHE WAS COMING FROM A MILITARY
BASE NEAR THE MISTY PALMS OASIS
AND HEADING TO BA SING SE.
IF WE RETRACE HER ROUTE
BACK TO THE BASE,
WE SHOULD FIND THE WRECKAGE.
- [snores]
- GUYS, IT'S THE WRECKAGE.
I FOUND IT.
THERE.
- THAT'S A BA SING SE AIRSHIP,
ALL RIGHT.
BUT WHERE'S THE REST OF IT?
- I DON'T KNOW,
BUT THERE ARE SOME TRACKS.
SEE? I TOLD YOU.
LANDING IS HARD.
- [gasps] SPIRITS.
- OKAY, GUYS, WE THINK KORRA
FOUND HER WAY BACK HERE.
NOW LET'S SPLIT OFF INTO TEAMS
AND SCOUR THE TOWN.
YES, WE'LL NEED YOUR HELP TOO,
PABU.
NOW JUST GIVE ME A SECOND
WHILE I--[gasps]
WAIT.
PABU?
PABU!
[laughs]
- WHY IS BOLIN HUGGING
THAT BIG RAT?
EW.
NOW HE'S KISSING IT.
- MWAH, MWAH, MWAH, MWAH.
I'M NEVER GONNA
LET YOU GO AGAIN.
- GUYS, LOOK OUT!
GIANT DOG-BEAST THINGY!
[all shout]
- OKAY, ALL RIGHT, NAGA.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU TOO.
AHH, STOP.
YOU'RE LICKING MY MOUTH.
[spits]
- ASAMI!
KORRA!
- YOU GUYS ARE OKAY!
SORRY, I WAS JUST--
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
- IT'S REALLY GOOD TO SEE
YOU TOO, BOTH OF YOU.
- GOOD.
YOU GUYS AREN'T DEAD.
- DON'T GET ALL MUSHY ON ME,
CHIEF.
TONRAQ, SIR.
- OH, MY GOSH.
IT'S LORD ZUKO.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
[whimpers]
- UH, FORGIVE MY BROTHER.
WE'RE JUST REALLY HONORED
TO MEET YOU, SIR.
- IT'S A PLEASURE TO MEET YOU
AS WELL.
- YOU MUST BE THE AVATAR.
MAKO TOLD ME SO MUCH
ABOUT YOU.
YOU ARE EVEN MORE BEAUTIFUL
THAN I IMAGINED.
- UH, ACTUALLY, THAT'S ASAMI.
THIS IS AVATAR KORRA.
KORRA, THIS IS
MY GRANDMA, YIN.
- YOU ARE VERY MUSCULAR
FOR A WOMAN.
- UM, THANKS.
YOU TOO?
- WHAT LOVELY YOUNG WOMEN.
MAKO, WHY AREN'T YOU DATING
ANY NICE GIRLS LIKE THEM?
- UH, SO WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOU TWO?
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
- WE WERE CAPTURED BY ZAHEER
AND TAKEN TO BA SING SE.
WE WERE THERE WHEN
THE EARTH QUEEN WAS OVERTHROWN.
- WHAT?
HOW DID YOU ESCAPE?
- ZAHEER LET US GO.
- WHY WOULD HE DO THAT?
- BECAUSE HE WANTED US TO
FIND YOU AND DELIVER A MESSAGE.
- ZAHEER IS HEADED TO THE
NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE AS WE SPEAK.
HE SAID HE'S GONNA WIPE OUT
THE NEW AIR NATION
AND EVERYONE IN IT, UNLESS YOU
TURN YOURSELF OVER TO HIM.
- ZAHEER'S THREATENING INNOCENT
LIVES, JUST TO GET TO ME.
- HE COULD BE BLUFFING.
- HE'S ALREADY TAKEN OUT
THE EARTH QUEEN.
I DON'T THINK HE BLUFFS.
- WE NEED TO RADIO TENZIN
AND WARN HIM THAT
THE RED LOTUS IS COMING.
- I AGREE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE DON'T HAVE A RADIO
ON THE AIRSHIP.
- THERE'S A PORTABLE RADIO
IN THE JEEP,
BUT THE SIGNAL WILL NEVER MAKE
IT TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
- WE NEED TO GET TO A PLACE THAT
HAS A STRONG RADIO TRANSMITTER.
THE METAL CLAN WILL HAVE ONE.
- LET'S GO.
WE'LL RADIO SU ON THE WAY.
HOPEFULLY SHE CAN GET AHOLD
OF TENZIN AT THE AIR TEMPLE
BY THE TIME WE GET TO ZAOFU.
DID YOU HAVE ANY LUCK
GETTING THROUGH TO TENZIN?
- NO ONE'S ANSWERING. WHAT IF
ZAHEER IS ALREADY UP THERE?
I SHOULD NEVER HAVE
LET OPAL GO.
- IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY, SU.
- I HOPE SO.
[radio static]
- WE HAVE A STRONG SIGNAL,
BUT NO ONE'S ANSWERING.
- I CAN'T JUST SIT AROUND HERE
WHILE A MADMAN
IS ON HIS WAY
TO THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.
- I'LL READY MY AIRSHIP.
WITH THE FULL FORCE
OF THE METAL CLAN SECURITY
BACKING US,
WE CAN TAKE THEM.
- WE'LL NEVER MAKE IT UP THERE
BEFORE ZAHEER.
- THERE MIGHT BE ANOTHER WAY
TO STOP HIM.
IT'S A LONG SHOT,
BUT ZAHEER IS ALWAYS MEDITATING
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD,
AND I KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE HE GOES: XAI BAU'S GROVE.
IF I COULD FIND HIM THERE,
MAYBE I COULD SOMEHOW TRAP HIM.
- WE CAN'T PROTECT YOU IN THERE.
I DON'T LIKE IT.
- I'LL BE FINE.
I HAVE TO TRY.
- I'LL WATCH OVER HER
AS SHE MEDITATES.
- I GUESS IN THE MEANTIME,
MAKO AND I WILL STAY HERE
AND TRY TO GET THROUGH
TO THE TEMPLE.
- WE'LL HELP SU
READY THE AIRSHIP.
- I'M GOING TO TAKE A NAP.
- ZAHEER, COME OUT!
FACE ME!
LEAVE THE AIRBENDERS
OUT OF THIS.
THERE YOU ARE.
- PLEASE DON'T HURT ME, KORRA.
I'M JUST AN OLD MAN.
- IROH?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I WAS JUST OUT SEARCHING
FOR A NEW TEAPOT
TO ADD TO MY COLLECTION,
BUT INSTEAD I FOUND YOU.
[laughs]
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD, YOU ALWAYS
SEEM TO FIND SOMETHING
YOU DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE LOOKING FOR.
YOU LOOK TROUBLED.
- I AM.
- SIT.
WHAT IS ON YOUR MIND?
- THERE'S A MANIAC ON THE LOOSE,
AND HE'S THREATENING TO DESTROY
THE NEW AIR NATION.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
- JUST BECAUSE YOU ARE
THE AVATAR
DOESN'T MEAN YOU WILL HAVE
ALL THE ANSWERS.
- I KNOW MANY AVATARS
HAVE NEEDED GUIDANCE,
BUT I'M THE ONLY ONE
SINCE AVATAR WAN
THAT CAN'T GET HELP
FROM MY PAST LIVES.
I WISH I COULD TALK TO AANG.
- YOU KNOW, ZUKO AND AANG
WERE CLOSE FRIENDS.
- LORD ZUKO, OF COURSE.
- YES, MY NEPHEW.
THEIR RELATIONSHIP STARTED OFF
A LITTLE ROCKY,
BUT THEY GREW
TO BECOME LIFELONG FRIENDS.
BEST FRIENDS.
- THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU'RE RIGHT
ABOUT THE SPIRIT WORLD.
I CAME HERE LOOKING
FOR SOMEONE ELSE,
BUT I'M GLAD I FOUND YOU.
- DID YOU FIND ZAHEER?
- NO, HE WASN'T THERE.
BUT THERE'S SOMEONE
I NEED TO TALK TO.
YOU'RE LEAVING?
AREN'T YOU COMING
TO THE AIR TEMPLE WITH US?
- I'M SORRY, BUT I CAN'T.
I'M GOING BACK
TO THE FIRE NATION.
IF IT'S TRUE THAT THE RED LOTUS
IS TARGETING
THE NATION'S LEADERS,
I NEED TO PROTECT MY DAUGHTER.
- I UNDERSTAND, YOU HAVE TO KEEP
THE FIRE LORD SAFE.
BUT BEFORE YOU LEAVE,
I WAS WONDERING IF YOU COULD
HELP ME WITH SOMETHING.
- I WAS OFTEN AANG'S COUNCIL,
AND I'D LOVE TO BE YOURS.
- THAT'S JUST IT, YOU KNEW AANG
BETTER THAN ANYONE.
I WAS WONDERING IF YOU KNEW
WHAT HE MIGHT DO
IF HE WERE IN MY SITUATION.
- HMM, REBUILDING THE AIR NATION
WAS AANG'S BIGGEST DREAM.
HE WOULD BE BESIDE HIMSELF
WITH JOY WITH WHAT YOU'VE DONE,
AND IF HE ACCOMPLISHED
THAT GOAL,
HE MIGHT HAVE SACRIFICED
ANYTHING TO PROTECT IT.
- SO HE WOULD GIVE HIMSELF UP
TO SAVE THE AIR NATION?
- I DON'T KNOW FOR SURE.
THE AIRBENDERS MIGHT HAVE BEEN
CLOSEST TO AANG'S HEART,
BUT AS THE AVATAR,
HE WAS CONCERNED
WITH PEOPLE OF ALL NATIONS.
NO ONE KNEW BETTER THAN AANG
THAT IN TIMES OF TURMOIL
THE WORLD NEEDS ITS AVATAR
THE MOST.
- THANKS.
YOUR UNCLE WAS RIGHT.
IT WAS HELPFUL TALKING TO YOU.
- WAIT, YOU SPOKE
WITH MY UNCLE?
- YES, IN THE SPIRIT WORLD.
A COUPLE OF TIMES ACTUALLY.
[footsteps approaching]
- GUYS, WE GOT THROUGH
TO THE AIR TEMPLE.
- WHO IS THIS?
- I TOLD YOU,
IT'S BOLIN!
- BOLIN'S NOT HERE RIGHT NOW,
CAN I TAKE A MESSAGE?
- NO, I'M NOT LOOKING FOR BOLIN,
I AM BOLIN!
AHH, LOOK, I NEED YOU
TO FIND YOUR DAD.
- HE'S OUTSIDE WITH THE BISON.
DID YOU KNOW WE FOUND
A WHOLE HERD FULL OF BABY BISON?
- NO.
A WHOLE HERD, REALLY?
[grunts]
- MEELO,
THIS IS YOUR COMMANDING OFFICER.
GO GET YOUR DAD, NOW.
- YES, SIR.
- COME ON.
COME ON.
- HELLO, THIS IS TENZIN.
- TENZIN, LISTEN TO ME
CAREFULLY.
ZAHEER IS ON HIS WAY
TO THE TEMPLE.
HE'S COMING
FOR THE AIRBENDERS.
YOU HAVE TO GET EVERYONE
OUT OF THERE IMMEDIATELY.
DROP EVERYTHING.
LEAVE NOW!
- OH, NO.
- WHAT? WHAT IS IT?
TENZIN!
TENZIN, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
- IT'S TOO LATE.
HE'S HERE.
- WHAT IS IT, DADDY?
- WE NEED TO GET EVERYONE
OUT OF HERE.
STAY CLOSE TO ME.
- WHAT'S GOING ON, TENZIN?
- IT'S ZAHEER.
ROUND EVERYONE UP.
WE NEED TO GET TO THE BISON
AND EVACUATE IMMEDIATELY.
- GUYS, WE GOT AN EMERGENCY.
WE'RE EVACUATING THE TEMPLE.
COME ON.
LOOK OUT!
[door opens]
- IT'S ZAHEER.
WE HAVE TO LEAVE.
- [screams]
- NO ONE'S GOING ANYWHERE,
OR SHE GETS IT.
- GOOD, THE ENTIRE FAMILY
IS HERE.
IT'S A PLEASURE TO FINALLY MEET
A TRUE AIRBENDING MASTER.
- WHAT IS IT
YOU WANT FROM US?
- NOTHING AT ALL.
IN FACT,
IF EVERYONE COOPERATES,
YOU WILL ALL WALK OUT
OF THIS SITUATION UNHARMED.
- THEN WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
- I WANT KORRA,
AND I'M TIRED OF CHASING HER.
- YOU'RE USING US AS LEVERAGE?
- YES.
- I WILL NEVER LET YOU
GET TO KORRA.
- UNFORTUNATELY,
YOU DON'T HAVE A CHOICE.
- YES, I DO.
[all grunt]
JINORA, GET EVERYONE
OUT OF HERE.
BUMI, KYA,
HELP ME HOLD THEM OFF.
AND STAY OUT
OF HER LINE OF SIGHT. GO. GO!
[bison growling]
- [grunts]
- IT'S TOO DANGEROUS--
WE'LL NEVER MAKE IT
TO THE STABLES
WITH HER UP THERE.
- [grunting]
- [strains]
[gasps]
- [screams]
- NO.
[grunts]
- [yells]
[both grunting]
- [screams]
- [yells]
- OOF!
- I SEE YOU'RE HAVING
AS MUCH FUN AS I AM.
- I CAN'T WAIT ANY LONGER.
- WAIT, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WHATEVER I CAN.
GET TO THE BISON!
GET OUT OF HERE!
- KAI!
NO.
- [yells]
[shouts]
[both scream]
I GOT YOU.
[strains]
[gasps]
- BUMI, LET GO.
- BUT WE COULD DIE.
- WE'RE GONNA DIE
IF WE HANG ON.
[both screaming]
- OOF.
- [grunts]
[yells]
[groans]
- GIVE UP.
IT'S OVER.
- AS LONG AS I'M BREATHING,
IT'S NOT OVER.
[grunting]
- [gasps]
WHOA!
THANKS, BUDDY.
YIP-YIP.