- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR
CAN MASTER ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
- THE NEW AIR NATION
IS IN JEOPARDY.
IN AN EFFORT TO FORCE KORRA
TO SURRENDER HERSELF,
ZAHEER AMBUSHED
THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
TENZIN, BUMI AND KYA ATTEMPTED
TO HOLD OFF THE RED LOTUS
BUT WERE INJURED IN BATTLE.
THE AIRBENDERS WERE UNABLE
TO ESCAPE
AND EVERYONE WAS TAKEN CAPTIVE,
EXCEPT KAI.
NOW KORRA AND TEAM AVATAR RACE
TO THE TEMPLE,
HOPING TO MOUNT A RESCUE.
- I SAY WE MAKE OUR APPROACH
FROM THE WEST.
DROP DOWN FROM THE AIRSHIP
ON CABLES.
AMBUSH THESE RED LOTUS LOWLIFES
BEFORE THEY KNOW WHAT HIT THEM.
- IT'LL NEVER WORK.
THAT COMBUSTION LADY
WILL PICK US OFF ONE BY ONE.
- YOU HAVE A BETTER IDEA
HOW TO SAVE THE AIRBENDERS?
- YEAH.
WE COME UP FROM THE VALLEY,
SCALE THE SIDE OF THE MOUNTAIN,
AND TAKE THEM OFF GUARD.
- THAT COULD WORK.
- AND GIVE THEM
THE HIGH GROUND? NO.
IF THEIR LAVABENDER SPOTS US,
HE'LL MELT THE MOUNTAINSIDE
AND US WITH IT.
- WAIT! I GOT IT.
I'LL DISGUISE MYSELF
AS A LOST HIKER.
AND ONCE I'M IN THE TEMPLE,
I'LL DISTRACT THE RED LOTUS
WITH MY BIRD CALLS.
[whistles a bird call]
CAW! CAW!
THAT'S WHEN YOU ALL STRIKE!
- BIRD CALLS?
REALLY?
- WELL, I HAVEN'T NOTICED YOU
OFFERING ANY SUGGESTIONS.
- IT DOESN'T MATTER. NONE OF
THESE IDEAS WILL WORK.
THE SECOND ZAHEER REALIZES
WE'RE UP TO SOMETHING,
HE'LL WIPE OUT THE AIRBENDERS.
- AND OPAL IS ONE
OF THOSE AIRBENDERS.
BELIEVE ME, I UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S AT STAKE.
- THEN I THINK YOU'LL AGREE.
THE ONLY PLAN THAT WILL WORK
IS FOR ME TO GIVE MYSELF UP.
- WHAT?
- KORRA, NO.
- WE'LL FIGURE OUT ANOTHER WAY.
- I TALKED IT OVER
WITH LORD ZUKO,
AND I'VE GIVEN IT
A LOT OF THOUGHT.
I HAVE TO DO THIS.
- YOU CAN'T EXPECT US TO SIT BY
AND JUST LET ZAHEER TAKE YOU.
- THE WORLD HAS BEEN OUT
OF BALANCE FOR FAR TOO LONG.
IT NEEDS THE AIR NATION
BACK AGAIN.
I CAN'T LET ZAHEER DESTROY IT
AND EVERYONE WE LOVE.
HELP ME SAVE THE AIRBENDERS.
THEN YOU CAN CAN WORRY
ABOUT SAVING ME.
- WE'RE WITH YOU, KORRA.
- YES, WHATEVER YOU NEED.
WE'RE HERE.
- I'LL GO RADIO ZAHEER.
[static over radio]
ZAHEER, ARE YOU THERE?
IT'S ME.
- I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOUR CALL.
SO DO WE HAVE A DEAL?
- YES.
YOU RELEASE THE AIRBENDERS,
AND THEN I'LL TURN MYSELF OVER.
- AND TAKE AWAY
THE ONLY LEVERAGE I HAVE?
NO.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
LISTEN CAREFULLY.
HERE'S WHAT I WANT YOU TO DO.
- WILL YOU SIT DOWN?
I'M ALREADY TENSE ENOUGH
AS IT IS!
- I'M JUST WORRIED ABOUT OPAL.
AND PABU'S NOT HERE
TO COMFORT ME.
I HOPE HE AND NAGA
ARE DOING OKAY BACK IN ZAOFU.
[Naga growling]
[Pabu squeaking]
- NO.
NOT MAKO'S SCARF!
BAD DOG AND RAT-THINGY!
[Naga whimpers]
I'M VERY DISAPPOINTED
IN YOU TWO.
[animals whine]
- DID YOU SPEAK TO ZAHEER?
- YES.
HE TOLD ME TO COME TO THE TOP OF
LAGHIMA'S PEAK AT NOON. ALONE.
ONCE HE HAS ME, HE'LL RELEASE
THE AIRBENDERS OVER TO YOU
AT THE TEMPLE.
I THINK I FIGURED OUT A WAY
TO PLAY THIS
SO THE AIRBENDERS AND KORRA
ALL COME OUT IN ONE PIECE.
- HOW?
- ZAHEER DOESN'T KNOW
HOW MANY OF US THERE ARE.
SO WE HAVE
THE NUMBERS ADVANTAGE.
I SAY WE SPLIT INTO TWO TEAMS.
MAKO, BOLIN AND ASAMI WILL TAKE
THE AIRSHIP UP TO THE TEMPLE.
MEANWHILE, MY METALBENDERS,
TONRAQ, LIN, AND I WILL GET
INTO POSITION
BELOW LAGHIMA'S PEAK.
- LET GO YOUR EARTHLY TETHER.
ENTER THE VOID.
EMPTY AND BECOME WIND.
- THE AIRBENDERS ARE SECURE.
- THANK YOU, P'LI.
FOR EVERYTHING.
- OF COURSE.
- I WANT YOU TO KNOW,
NOT ONE DAY WENT BY
IN THAT PRISON
WHEN I DIDN'T THINK OF YOU.
- THE YEARS APART ONLY MADE
MY LOVE FOR YOU STRONGER.
AND, DEEP DOWN, I KNEW YOU'D
FIND A WAY TO GET ME OUT.
JUST LIKE YOU SAVED ME
FROM BECOMING
THAT WARLORD'S KILLING MACHINE
WHEN I WAS A GIRL.
YOU'VE SHOWN ME
WHAT TRUE FREEDOM MEANS.
- AND, AFTER TODAY,
WE'LL SHOW THE ENTIRE WORLD
WHAT IT MEANS.
NO MORE PRISONS.
NO MORE RUNNING.
- I LOVE YOU, ZAHEER.
- I LOVE YOU TOO.
- RADIO THE SECOND YOU SEE
THOSE AIRBENDERS.
- I WILL, CHIEF.
GOOD LUCK.
[armor clanking]
- BE CAREFUL, KORRA.
- YOU TOO.
- [whimpering]
- KORRA.
- DON'T WORRY, DAD.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
- I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
HOW PROUD I AM OF YOU.
THE RISK YOU'RE TAKING
TO SAVE THE AIR NATION
WILL BE REMEMBERED
FOR GENERATIONS.
- I LOVE YOU, DAD.
- I LOVE YOU TOO, SWEETHEART.
- AND, DAD.
WATCH OUT FOR ZAHEER.
HE'S NOT VERY FOND
OF WORLD LEADERS.
- I CAN HANDLE HIM.
JUST STAY FOCUSED
ON YOUR MISSION.
- OH, MAN.
- MUST HAVE BEEN SOME FIGHT.
[static over radio]
- MAKO, DO YOU SEE
THE AIRBENDERS?
- NOT YET.
WE'RE JUST ARRIVING.
DON'T TURN YOURSELF OVER
UNTIL I GET A VISUAL ON THEM.
- [grunting]
- THIS WAY.
YOU WANT THE AIRBENDERS OR NOT?
[wind whistling]
- DROP YOUR STAFF
AND SURRENDER YOURSELF.
DON'T MAKE ME COME GET YOU.
[static over radio]
- MAKO.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- THEY'RE HERE.
BUT SO IS THE LAVABENDER.
- TELL GHAZAN
TO LET THE AIRBENDERS GO.
- NOT UNTIL
YOU TURN YOURSELF OVER.
THIS ISN'T A NEGOTIATION.
WIPE THEM OUT.
- NO! WAIT!
I'M COMING.
- STAND DOWN.
- AND DON'T BOTHER TRYING
TO METALBEND OUT OF THESE.
THEY'RE PLATINUM.
- [grunts]
- WE HAVE HER.
[groaning]
- IT'S OKAY, TENZIN.
WE'RE ABOUT TO GET YOU
OUT OF HERE.
[water runs]
[all gasp]
[water rushing]
- KORRA, IT WAS A TRICK!
THEY'RE NOT HERE!
DON'T TURN YOURSELF OVER!
- WE HAD A DEAL!
[grunts]
- CHIEF, GET KORRA
OUT OF THERE NOW!
- GO! GO!
- [grunts]
[grunts]
- GET THE AVATAR ON THE AIRSHIP.
I'LL DEAL WITH THEM.
[both scream]
- [grunts]
- [screams]
- NOWHERE TO GO, ZAHEER!
- WHERE ARE THE AIRBENDERS?
- I DON'T KNOW.
ZAHEER MOVED THEM
OUT OF THE TEMPLE.
- WILL YOU JUST BURY THEM
ALREADY?
- COME ON.
WE HAVE TO GET BACK
TO THE AIRSHIP!
- NOT GONNA HAPPEN!
THE EXIT'S BLOCKED!
[column crashes]
- [grunts]
- WHERE'S OOGI?
- GONE.
ALL THE BISON GOT SCARED OFF
DURING THE ATTACK.
BUT I THINK I KNOW
ANOTHER WAY OUT.
BOLIN, CAN YOU GET US
THROUGH THAT WALL?
- ON IT!
[lava gurgling]
- THROUGH THERE.
- [sighing]
IS IT JUST ME?
OR IS IT, UH, GETTING
REALLY WARM IN HERE?
OH, THIS IS NOT GOOD.
LET'S MOVE IT, PEOPLE!
- [grunts]
SAY HELLO
TO THE EARTH QUEEN FOR ME.
- [groans]
- DAD!
- WE'RE PINNED DOWN!
- I'M GONNA DRAW HER FIRE.
YOU TAKE HER OUT.
- LIN, NO.
- I LOVE YOU.
COME AND GET ME,
YOU THIRD-EYED FREAK!
OOH!
[groans]
[metal clangs]
- P'LI!
- [grunting]
- IT'S OVER, ZAHEER.
- LET GO YOUR EARTHLY TETHER.
- RELEASE THE AVATAR!
- ENTER THE VOID.
- THIS IS YOUR LAST WARNING!
- EMPTY AND BECOME WIND.
- NO! STOP!
- DID HE JUST FLY?
- GUESS HE DOESN'T NEED A RIDE.
- [groaning]
- KORRA.
- WE CAN'T OUTRUN IT!
THIS WAY!
- NOW WHAT?
- [grunts]
- BOLIN!
- [screams]
YAH!
- INCREDIBLE.
- YOU'RE A LAVABENDER.
- I KNOW.
I JUST FOUND OUT.
[bison growls]
- HEY, YOU GUYS NEED A LIFT?
- KAI. YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
- MORE OR LESS.
EVERYONE HOP ON.
[bison groans]
[rocks crumble]
- I OWE YOU MY LIFE.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
- YOU CAN CALL ME KUVIRA.
- CAW! CAW!
CAW! CAW!
[all screaming]
- [grunts]
- HEY, EVERYBODY.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I GOTTA TELL YOU.
- HOW DID YOU GUYS MAKE IT
OUT OF THAT TEMPLE ALIVE?
- IT WAS ALL BOLIN.
I THOUGHT WE WERE DONE FOR.
THEN OUT OF NOWHERE,
HE LAVABENDS.
- I KNEW YOU HAD THE POTENTIAL
FOR SOMETHING BIG.
YOU JUST HAD TO BELIEVE
IN YOURSELF.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
BEING MOMENTS FROM DEATH
WAS A PRETTY GOOD MOTIVATOR TOO.
OF COURSE, WE NEVER WOULD HAVE
MADE IT BACK WITHOUT KAI.
- GLAD I COULD HELP.
SO ANYWAY--
- DID ZAHEER GET AWAY
WITH KORRA?
- I'M AFRAID SO.
- APPARENTLY, HE CAN FLY NOW.
- WHAT?
- HOW?
- ARE YOU SURE?
- I WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT EITHER
IF I HADN'T SEEN IT FOR MYSELF.
- I'VE HEARD THE LEGENDS ABOUT
GURU LAGHIMA'S ABILITY TO FLY.
BUT I NEVER IMAGINED
THEY WERE TRUE.
- SO WHAT'S OUR NEXT MOVE?
- I HAVE AN IDEA.
- NOT RIGHT NOW, KID!
WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT WHERE
ZAHEER TOOK KORRA.
- AND FIND THE AIRBENDERS.
- THAT'S WHAT
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO TELL YOU!
I KNOW WHERE THE AIRBENDERS ARE,
AND I BET IT'S WHERE
KORRA IS TOO!
- WELL, WHY DIDN'T YOU
SAY SOMETHING?
- [scoffs]
- WHERE ARE THEY?
HOW DID YOU FIND THEM?
- AFTER I GOT BLASTED
OUT OF THE SKY,
I WOKE UP ON THE SIDE
OF THE MOUNTAIN,
WHERE THIS LITTLE FELLOW
FOUND ME.
[bison whinnies]
I TRIED TO SNEAK BACK
INTO THE TEMPLE
TO SEE IF I COULD RESCUE
EVERYONE,
AND THAT'S WHEN
I SAW THE AIRSHIP LEAVING.
I FOLLOWED IT TO SOME CAVES
A FEW MILES FROM HERE.
THAT GIANT LADY MET UP
WITH SOME PEOPLE
WHO TOOK THE AIRBENDERS
INTO THE CAVES.
- WAS IT GHAZAN AND MING-HUA?
- NO, THERE WERE FOUR MORE
OF THEM.
DIDN'T LOOK FAMILIAR.
- MUST BE MORE RED LOTUS MEMBERS
THAN WE THOUGHT.
- I COULDN'T FIGHT THEM ALL
ON MY OWN.
SO I CAME BACK HERE,
HOPING YOU GUYS WOULD SHOW UP.
- WE NEED TO GET TO THOSE CAVES.
- HOW? I DON'T THINK
WE CAN ALL FIT ON MY BISON.
[bison grumbles]
- OOGI!
[bison purrs]
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU TOO,
OLD FRIEND.
- I WANNA COME WITH YOU.
- NO, KUVIRA.
STAY WITH THE INJURED.
WE'LL BE BACK FOR YOU
ONCE WE HAVE THE AVATAR.
[bison grunts]
- HEY, UM, I APPRECIATE YOU
COMING BACK FOR US.
SORRY FOR EVER GIVING YOU
A HARD TIME.
- THAT'S OKAY.
I PROBABLY DESERVED IT.
- YEAH, YOU KINDA DID.
[bison whinnying]
- WHY DIDN'T YOU EVER TELL US
YOU CAN FLY?
- I WASN'T SURE I COULD.
ONLY ONE OTHER AIRBENDER
IN HISTORY HAD THE ABILITY.
- HOW'D YOU FIGURE OUT
HOW TO DO IT?
- I FOUND TRUE FREEDOM.
I AM NO LONGER BOUND TO
THIS EARTH BY WORLDLY DESIRES.
I HAVE ENTERED THE VOID.
- WHERE'S P'LI?
- SHE SACRIFICED HER LIFE
FOR OUR CAUSE.
NOW LET'S MAKE SURE
IT WASN'T IN VAIN.
- [gasps]
YOU...
YOU KILLED MY FATHER.
[screams]
- I UNDERSTAND YOUR GRIEF.
I ALSO LOST
SOMEONE I LOVED TODAY.
BUT YOUR PAIN WILL SOON BE OVER.
BRING THE POISON.
- [gasps]