- Tenzin: EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
THE RED LOTUS HAS CAPTURED
THE AVATAR.
KORRA GAVE HERSELF UP IN
EXCHANGE FOR THE AIRBENDERS,
BUT ZAHEER DOUBLE-CROSSED HER,
WHILE GHAZAN TRAPPED
TEAM AVATAR IN THE TEMPLE.
ALL SEEMED LOST
UNTIL BOLIN SAVED THEIR LIVES
BY LAVABENDING.
BUT HE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE
WITH NEW SKILLS...
ZAHEER UNLOCKED THE ANCIENT
AIRBENDING ABILITY OF FLIGHT.
WILL TEAM AVATAR SAVE THE AIR NATION
AND KORRA BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE?
WHEN I GET OUT OF HERE,
NONE OF YOU WILL SURVIVE!
- YOU WON'T GET OUT.
UNLESS THE METAL CLAN TAUGHT
YOU A WAY TO BEND PLATINUM.
ONCE WE ADMINISTER
THIS POISON,
YOUR BODY WILL
NATURALLY REACT,
FORCING YOU
INTO THE AVATAR STATE
IN AN EFFORT
TO KEEP YOU ALIVE.
SADLY FOR YOU,
YOU'LL BE ENTERING IT
FOR THE LAST TIME.
- NO.
THE AVATAR CYCLE...
- YES.
WHEN WE DISPATCH YOU
IN THE AVATAR STATE,
THE CYCLE WILL END.
SO WE LUCKY FEW,
THIS BAND OF BROTHERS
AND SISTERS IN ANARCHY,
ARE WITNESSING THE BEGINNING
OF AN ERA OF TRUE FREEDOM.
TOGETHER WE WILL FORGE A WORLD
WITHOUT KINGS AND QUEENS,
WITHOUT BORDERS OR NATIONS,
WHERE A MAN'S ONLY ALLEGIANCE
IS TO HIMSELF
AND THOSE HE LOVES.
WE WILL RETURN TO THE TRUE
BALANCE OF NATURAL ORDER.
AND THOUGH YOU
WILL NEVER AGAIN BE REBORN,
YOUR NAME WILL ECHO
THROUGHOUT HISTORY.
KORRA, THE LAST AVATAR.
DID YOU FIND ANY WAY
TO ESCAPE?
- NO, NOT YET.
BUT DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL FIND A WAY OUT SOON.
THEY MIGHT NOT
MAKE IT THAT LONG.
KORRA WILL COME TO SAVE US,
RIGHT?
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO DO THIS ON OUR OWN.
- ADMINISTER THE POISON.
AH.
AHH!
- GET READY.
AS SOON AS SHE'S IN THE AVATAR
STATE, TAKE HER OUT.
- WAIT.
WHY ISN'T SHE STAYING
IN THE AVATAR STATE?
- GIVE IT TIME.
SHE CAN'T RESIST FOR LONG.
THE PLACE WHERE I SAW THEM
TAKING THE AIRBENDERS
IS AROUND HERE.
THAT'S GOTTA BE WHERE
THEY TOOK KORRA.
- Kai: THAT'S IT!
DOWN THERE, LEFTY.
FIND THE AIRBENDERS
AND MY FAMILY.
- DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT COMING OUT
WITHOUT OUR CHILDREN
AND THE REST OF YOUR PEOPLE.
- IT'S WORKING.
- Amon: I TOLD YOU, KORRA.
THE WORLD DOESN'T NEED YOU
ANYMORE.
THE TIME OF THE AVATAR
IS OVER, KORRA.
GIVE UP.
YOU'RE TOO WEAK TO RESIST
AND I'M STRONGER THAN EVER.
THERE'S NO USE FIGHTING.
LET GO.
All: LET GO.
- I'M THIRSTY.
- I GOTTA GO PEE.
- ME TOO.
HEY.
KEEP IT DOWN OVER THERE
OR YOU'RE ALL GOING
TO END UP LIKE THEM.
SIR, PLEASE.
COULD WE JUST HAVE SOME WATER?
THERE ARE CHILDREN
AND A BABY HERE.
- AH!
OH, SO YOU JUST CALLED
ME OVER TO ATTACK ME.
FINE.
NOW NOBODY GETS ANY WATER.
AH.
I DON'T KNOW HOW WE ENDED
UP HERE IN DAY CARE
WHILE EVERYONE ELSE GETS TO
WATCH THE AVATAR BEING DESTROYED.
I CAN HOLD A BOWL OF POISON.
- HEY!
WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
- AH!
- MOM!
OH, HONEY,
I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE SAFE.
OH!
- ME TOO.
YOU'RE ALIVE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
- WHY?
JUST BECAUSE I WAS BLOWN
OUT OF THE SKY
AND FELL HUNDREDS OF FEET
DOWN A CLIFF?
DON'T YOU KNOW IT TAKES MORE
THAN THAT TO GET RID OF ME?
WE HAVE TO GET THESE TWO
OUT OF HERE NOW.
THEY DON'T LOOK SO GOOD.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I FEEL GREAT.
YOU GUYS GET EVERYONE
OUT OF HERE.
I'LL SEARCH FOR KORRA.
- WE'RE GOING WITH YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SEARCH
FOR HER.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHERE
SHE'S BEING HELD.
- NOW!
DESTROY THE AVATAR.
UGH.
AH!
- KORRA.
WE HAVE TO HELP HER!
- LOOK OUT!
YOU HELP KORRA.
WE GOT THIS.
DADDY!
OH, THANK GOODNESS
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
- HONEY, ARE YOU OKAY?
- I'LL BE FINE.
- WE HAVE TO HELP KORRA.
AH!
WHAT ARE YOU SMILING ABOUT?
I WAS JUST REMEMBERING
THE LAST TIME WE FOUGHT.
WELL, A LOT HAS CHANGED
SINCE THEN.
SO THAT'S HOW
YOU GOT OUT OF THE TEMPLE.
NOT BAD.
LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU'VE GOT.
YOU CAN'T FIGHT ME
AND THE POISON.
I CAN FLY UP ON MY BISON
TO HELP HER.
YOU'D NEVER BE ABLE
TO KEEP UP WITH ZAHEER.
HE'S TOO POWERFUL.
- WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.
- HOW CAN HE FLY LIKE THAT?
HE'S UNLOCKED POWERS
OF AIRBENDING
THAT HAVEN'T EXISTED
FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS.
THERE HAVEN'T BEEN
THIS MANY AIRBENDERS
IN ONE PLACE
FOR A LONG TIME, EITHER.
WE HAVE POWER TOGETHER.
HURRY!
EVERYONE FORM A CIRCLE.
FOLLOW ME.
AH!
- YOU HAVE NO WATER.
IT'S OVER.
- NOT YET.
NOW IT'S OVER!
- AH!
GIVE UP GHAZAN, YOU CAN'T WIN!
I'M NEVER GOING BACK
TO PRISON.
IF I'M GOING DOWN TODAY,
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
- MAKO, HANG ON.
AH!
THE POISON
HAS DONE ITS WORK.
THE AVATAR CYCLE
WILL BE OVER MOMENTARILY.
AH!
- AH.
- KORRA, SWEETHEART,
IT'S ME, DAD.
PLEASE HANG ON.
- WHAT ARE YOU LAUGHING ABOUT?
- YOU'RE TOO LATE!
THE POISON'S BEEN
IN HER SYSTEM TOO LONG.
THE RED LOTUS HAS WON.
YOU CAN SAVE HER.
THE POISON IS METALLIC.
DAD?
YOU'RE ALIVE.
- I'M HERE FOR YOU.
I'M NEVER GOING TO LET YOU GO.
- Zaheer: NO!
NO!
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE REVOLUTION
HAS ALREADY BEGUN.
CHAOS IS THE
NATURAL ORDER OF...
YOU SEE WHAT I DID THERE?
I PUT A SOCK IN IT.
LITERALLY.
- CLASSIC BOLIN.
- I DO WHAT I DO.
- THERE YOU GO.
ALL FIXED UP FOR A FORMAL
AVATAR APPEARANCE.
TAKE A LOOK.
- IT'S GREAT.
THANKS.
YOU KNOW, NOBODY EXPECTS YOU
TO BOUNCE BACK RIGHT AWAY.
IT'S ONLY BEEN TWO WEEKS.
YOU NEED TIME TO HEAL.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I'M HERE FOR YOU.
IF YOU EVER WANT TO TALK,
OR ANYTHING.
BUT LET'S JUST TRY
TO ENJOY THIS TODAY.
FOR JINORA.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
OKAY.
LET'S GO.
- YOU LOOK BEAUTIFUL, SWEETIE.
YOU'RE LOOKING STRONGER
EVERY DAY, KORRA.
I'D LIKE TO OFFICIALLY
WELCOME YOU BACK TO REPUBLIC CITY.
I KNOW THAT THE LAST TIME
WE SAW EACH OTHER
IT DIDN'T END
ON THE BEST TERMS,
BUT I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR TAKING DOWN
THOSE RED LOTUS TERRORISTS.
- WE SHOULD GO INSIDE.
- I CAN HELP.
- I WANNA RIDE WITH KORRA.
JINORA'S ALREADY INSIDE.
IT SMELLS LIKE SHOE TREES.
- SANDALWOOD, MEELO.
- I GOT THIS.
HANG IN THERE, KID.
- SHE'S NOT LOOKING GOOD.
NEITHER WOULD YOU IF YOU'D
GONE THROUGH WHAT SHE HAD.
- SHE'LL BE FINE.
SHE JUST NEEDS TIME TO HEAL.
THE POISON TOOK A GREAT TOLL.
- OF COURSE.
I'M JUST SAYING,
WITH THE EARTH KINGDOM
IN COMPLETE DISARRAY
SINCE THE LOSS OF THE QUEEN...
AND EVEN WITH ZAHEER
LOCKED UP AGAIN,
WE STILL DON'T KNOW
HOW MANY RED LOTUS MEMBERS
MIGHT BE OUT THERE, HIDING.
- EXACTLY.
WITH THE WORLD GETTING MORE
AND MORE DANGEROUS,
WE NEED THE AVATAR
NOW MORE THAN EVER.
WHO WILL PROTECT US
WHILE SHE'S IN A WHEELCHAIR?
- JINORA, COME FORWARD.
TODAY WE WELCOME THE FIRST
AIRBENDING MASTER IN A GENERATION,
AND I COULDN'T BE MORE PROUD
OF MY DAUGHTER.
WHEN THE EXISTENCE OF
OUR PEOPLE WAS THREATENED,
WHEN THE AVATAR'S LIFE
HUNG IN THE BALANCE,
JINORA NEVER GAVE UP HOPE.
THANKS TO HER LEADERSHIP, I SEE A VERY
BRIGHT FUTURE FOR THE AIR NATION.
OF COURSE, THERE WOULD BE NO AIR
NATION WITHOUT AVATAR KORRA.
SHE OPENED THE PORTALS AND SOMEHOW
THE WORLD BEGAN ANEW FOR US.
AND SHE WAS EVEN WILLING
TO LAY DOWN HER OWN LIFE
IN ORDER TO PROTECT OURS.
THERE'S NO WAY WE CAN EVER
REPAY HER FOR ALL SHE'S DONE.
BUT WE CAN FOLLOW HER EXAMPLE
OF SERVICE AND SACRIFICE.
SO WHILE SHE RECUPERATES,
THE AIR NATION WILL RECLAIM ITS
NOMADIC ROOTS AND ROAM THE EARTH.
BUT UNLIKE OUR ANCESTORS,
WE WILL SERVE PEOPLE
OF ALL NATIONS,
WORKING WHEREVER THERE IS
CORRUPTION AND DISCORD,
TO RESTORE BALANCE AND PEACE.
AVATAR KORRA,
I VOW THAT WE WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN OUR POWER
TO FOLLOW IN YOUR FOOTSTEPS
AND BRING HARMONY
TO THE WORLD.
NOW, LET US ANOINT THE MASTER
WHO WILL HELP LEAD US
IN OUR NEW PATH.