- EARTH. FIRE.
AIR. WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
[dramatic music]
- THE AVATAR HAS GONE MISSING!
THREE YEARS AGO,
ZAHEER POISONED KORRA,
SEVERELY INJURING HER.
WHILE HER FRIENDS MOVED ON
WITH THEIR LIVES,
KORRA REMAINED
IN THE SOUTH POLE.
EVERYONE THOUGHT
SHE WAS STILL RECUPERATING,
BUT SIX MONTHS AGO, KORRA LEFT
HOME AND HASN'T BEEN SEEN SINCE.
EVEN CHIEF TONRAQ
WAS SHOCKED TO LEARN
THAT HIS DAUGHTER'S WHEREABOUTS
ARE UNKNOWN.
WHAT HAS BECOME OF THE AVATAR
AND WHEN WILL SHE RETURN?
[squeaking]
- [knocking]
HURRY UP IN THERE!
COME ON, I GOT
AN EMERGENCY SITUATION!
- KNOCK YOURSELF OUT.
- [whimpering]
[horn blows]
- [breathing heavily]
HUH?
[dramatic music]
YOU AGAIN.
[yelling]
LEAVE ME ALONE!
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH HER?
- YOUNG LADY,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
CAN I TAKE YOU TO A DOCTOR?
- NO, I DON'T NEED ANY HELP.
[dramatic music]
- NOW DON'T TAKE THIS
THE WRONG WAY,
BUT I CAN'T WAIT
FOR YOU TO LEAVE.
- HOW ELSE IS SHE SUPPOSED
TO TAKE THAT BUT THE WRONG WAY?
- I MEAN BECAUSE I'VE NEVER
HAD A PEN PAL BEFORE.
I'M GOING TO WRITE YOU
SO MANY LETTERS,
AND JUST TO GET
THE BALL ROLLING,
HERE.
SPOILER ALERT.
PABU AND I
ALREADY MISS YOU.
- THANKS, THAT'S SWEET.
- ARE YOU SURE YOU DON'T WANT
SOME COMPANY IN
THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE?
I'M HAPPY TO COME WITH YOU.
- NO, I APPRECIATE IT,
BUT I'LL ONLY BE GONE
A COUPLE WEEKS.
A LITTLE TIME ALONE
WILL BE GOOD FOR ME.
- NOW I DON'T WANT YOU TO WORRY
ABOUT A THING WHILE YOU'RE GONE.
YOUR RECOVERY SHOULD BE
YOUR NUMBER ONE CONCERN.
JINORA, THE AIRBENDERS AND I
HAVE EVERYTHING UNDER CONTROL.
[ship horn blows]
- BYE, KORRA!
- GET BETTER SOON!
- DON'T FORGET TO WRITE!
[melancholy music]
♪ ♪
- [moaning]
AH!
[breathing heavily]
[somber music]
- CAN'T SLEEP AGAIN?
HONEY, YOUR FATHER AND I
HAVE TRIED TO GIVE YOU
AS MUCH SPACE AS YOU'VE NEEDED,
BUT WE'RE WORRIED.
YOU'RE NOT SLEEPING.
YOU'RE BARELY EATING.
WE DON'T WANT TO PUSH YOU,
BUT IT'S BEEN THREE WEEKS.
WILL YOU PLEASE GO SEE KATARA?
- ALL RIGHT.
I'LL GO.
- YOU'RE GOING
TO GET THROUGH THIS.
OH, I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
- THE POISON DID A LOT
OF INTERNAL DAMAGE.
- CAN YOU FIX IT?
- I CAN HELP GUIDE
YOUR HEALING PROCESS,
BUT WHETHER YOU GET BETTER
OR NOT IS UP TO YOU.
[water splashes]
I KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO GO
THROUGH A TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE,
AND I PROMISE YOU,
IF YOU DEDICATE YOURSELF
TO GETTING BETTER,
YOU'LL RECOVER
STRONGER THAN EVER.
- THAT'S WHAT I WANT,
MORE THAN ANYTHING.
- THEN TRY SOMETHING FOR ME.
CONCENTRATE ON YOUR BIG TOE.
VISUALIZE IT MOVING.
BREATHE.
[inhales and exhales]
[flute music]
- [gasps]
DID YOU SEE THAT?
IT WORKED!
- THE MIND CAN BE
A POWERFUL ALLY
OR YOUR GREATEST ENEMY.
NOW, I WANT YOU TO TRY
TAKING A STEP.
- [grunting]
AH!
[screams]
UGH!
- YOU'RE OKAY.
YOUR BODY THINKS
IT'S STILL IN DANGER,
BUT YOU'RE SAFE HERE.
USE YOUR MIND
TO OVERCOME THE PAIN.
TRY AGAIN.
- I'M DONE FOR TODAY.
- "DEAR KORRA, I MISS YOU.
"IT'S NOT THE SAME
IN REPUBLIC CITY WITHOUT YOU.
"HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
THINGS ARE GOING WELL HERE.
"I JUST GOT A BIG CONTRACT
"TO HELP REDESIGN
THE CITY'S INFRASTRUCTURE,
SO I'LL BE KEEPING
PRETTY BUSY FOR AWHILE."
- "HEY, KORRA.
"SO, I'M NOT VERY GOOD
AT WRITING LETTERS.
"IT'S 2:15 IN THE AFTERNOON.
WEATHER IS FAIR.
"CHANCE OF SNOW SHOWERS
LATER TODAY.
"BUT ENOUGH JOKING AROUND.
I HOPE YOU'RE DOING WELL.
"ME?
I'M BACK ON THE BEAT.
"BEIFONG HAS ME STAKING OUT
THE RED MONSOON HIDEOUT,
YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT'S GOING DOWN."
- "MY DEAREST, AVATAR KORRA.
"THOUGH SEVERAL FORTNIGHTS HAVE
PASSED SINCE YOUR DEPARTURE,
"TO CONVALESCE IN THE HOMELAND
OF YOUR TRIBESMEN,
"I FEEL OUR FRIENDSHIP KNOWS
NEITHER TIME NOR DISTANCE.
"YOU WILL BE
MOST PLEASED TO LEARN
"THAT I FOUND GAINFUL EMPLOYMENT
"WITH SIR VARRICK
AND THE LADY KUVIRA.
"I SET OFF ON THE MORROW
WITH SOME TREPIDATION,
"BUT I AM EAGER TO OFFER
ANY AID I CAN
IN STABILIZING
THE EARTH KINGDOM."
- WHENEVER YOU'RE READY.
- WHAT'S THE POINT?
WE'VE BEEN AT THIS
FOR ALMOST SIX MONTHS
AND I CAN BARELY TAKE A COUPLE
OF STEPS WITHOUT COLLAPSING.
- I KNOW YOU'RE FRUSTRATED,
BUT...
- OF COURSE I'M FRUSTRATED!
A CRAZY MAN POISONED ME,
AND NOW I CAN'T DRESS MYSELF
OR COOK FOR MYSELF
OR DO ANYTHING FOR MYSELF,
AND THIS WHOLE TIME
MY FRIENDS HAVE BEEN OFF
HELPING THE WORLD
WHILE I'M STUCK WITH YOU,
AND YOU CAN'T EVEN HEAL ME!
THAT CAME OUT WRONG.
- IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LET YOUR ANGER AND FRUSTRATION
FLOW LIKE WATER.
- I AM TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
WHY THIS HAPPENED TO ME.
BUT NOTHING MAKES ANY SENSE.
I'M TIRED, KATARA.
I'M SO TIRED.
- KORRA, I KNOW YOU FEEL
ALONE RIGHT NOW,
BUT YOU'RE NOT THE FIRST AVATAR
WHO'S HAD TO OVERCOME
GREAT SUFFERING.
CAN YOU IMAGINE HOW MUCH PAIN
AANG FELT WHEN HE LEARNED
THAT HIS ENTIRE CULTURE
WAS TAKEN FROM HIM?
- THAT MUST HAVE BEEN SO AWFUL.
- BUT HE NEVER LET IT
DESTROY HIS SPIRIT.
HE CHOSE TO FIND MEANING
IN HIS SUFFERING,
AND EVENTUALLY FOUND PEACE.
- AND WHAT AM I GONNA FIND
IF I GET THROUGH THIS?
- I DON'T KNOW, BUT WON'T IT
BE INTERESTING TO FIND OUT?
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
VISUALIZE YOURSELF
WALKING OVER TO NAGA.
- [whimpers]
- CAN YOU SEE IT?
- YES.
- NOW, TAKE THAT FIRST STEP.
- [grunting]
- [barks]
- WHERE'D YOU COME FROM,
LITTLE CUTIE?
- [panting]
[growls]
- YOU CAN SEE HER, TOO?
- [growling]
- IF YOU CAN SEE HER, TOO,
MAYBE I'M NOT GOING CRAZY.
- [barking]
[growling]
- HOW'D YOU DO THAT?
- [panting]
[barks]
- YOU WANT ME TO FOLLOW YOU?
- [barking]
- ALL RIGHT,
LET'S SEE WHAT I FIND.
- [rumbling]
- IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
- HOW HAVE YOU BEEN, KORRA.
YOU LOOK GREAT.
- I FEEL GREAT.
COME ON.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU
HOW MUCH BETTER I'M DOING.
[shouting]
ATTACK!
I CAN TAKE IT.
- AH! AH!
- ALL RIGHT,
THE SPARRING MATCH IS OVER.
- I THOUGHT I WAS READY.
- THERE IS NO SHAME
IN TAKING THE TIME YOU NEED
TO MAKE A FULL RECOVERY.
BEING THE AVATAR CAN WAIT.
- BUT WHAT ABOUT
THE EARTH KINGDOM?
I HEAR IT'S STILL
A MESS OUT THERE.
- THE SITUATION
HAS BEEN STABILIZING
SINCE KUVIRA TOOK CHARGE.
- BUT THAT SHOULD BE ME OUT
THERE FIXING THINGS, NOT HER.
- I KNOW YOU WANT TO HELP,
BUT TRUST ME,
EVERYONE HAS THIS UNDER CONTROL.
I JUST THINK YOU NEED TO...
- IF YOU SAY, "BE PATIENT,"
I SWEAR I'M GONNA
WATER-SMACK YOU IN THE MOUTH.
- NO, I WAS GOING
TO SAY YOU NEED TO...
NOT WORRY ABOUT THE FUTURE.
BE GRATEFUL
FOR WHERE YOU ARE NOW
AND THE PROGRESS YOU'VE MADE.
- "DEAR ASAMI, I'M SORRY
I HAVEN'T WRITTEN TO YOU SOONER,
"BUT EVERY TIME I'VE TRIED,
I NEVER KNEW WHAT TO SAY.
"THE PAST TWO YEARS HAVE BEEN
THE HARDEST OF MY LIFE.
"EVEN THOUGH I CAN
GET AROUND FINE NOW,
"I STILL CAN'T GO INTO
THE AVATAR STATE.
"I KEEP HAVING VISIONS OF ZAHEER
AND WHAT HAPPENED THAT DAY.
"KATARA THINKS A LOT OF THIS
IS IN MY HEAD,
"SO I'VE BEEN MEDITATING A LOT,
"BUT SOMETIMES I WORRY
I'LL NEVER FULLY RECOVER.
"PLEASE DON'T TELL
MAKO AND BOLIN
"I WROTE TO YOU AND NOT THEM.
"I DON'T WANT
TO HURT THEIR FEELINGS,
"BUT IT'S EASIER TO TELL YOU
ABOUT THIS STUFF.
I DON'T THINK
THEY'D UNDERSTAND."
[silverware clinks]
- EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT, SWEETIE?
- THERE'S SOMETHING
I NEED TO TELL YOU BOTH.
- WHAT IS IT?
- I WANT TO GO BACK
TO REPUBLIC CITY.
- ARE YOU SURE?
- I KNOW I'M NOT 100% YET,
BUT I FEEL LIKE I'VE HIT A WALL.
I NEED TO BE
WHERE THE ACTION IS,
WHERE MY FRIENDS ARE.
- I'LL HAVE THE WHITE LOTUS
PREPARE A BOAT
AND THEY CAN TAKE YOU BACK
TO REPUBLIC CITY
AS SOON AS YOU'RE READY.
- NO, I WANT TO GO ALONE.
AND HAVE SOME TIME
TO CLEAR MY HEAD.
IT WILL BE GOOD FOR ME.
- [howling]
- TWO LOBSTER CRABS, PLEASE.
- WHY, YOU'RE THE AVATAR,
AIN'T YA?
- YEP, THAT'S ME.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT!
MIND IF I TAKE A PICTURE
FOR MY WALL OF AVATARS?
- I'M KIND OF IN A HURRY.
- IT'LL ONLY TAKE A SECOND.
AVATAR AANG WAS A BIG FAN
OF MY SEAWEED WRAPS, YOU KNOW,
SO I NAMED THEM "AANG ROLLS."
NOW THEY'RE MY BIGGEST SELLER.
AND THEY AIN'T EVEN GOT
FISH IN 'EM.
NOW SMILE.
- BUT IF COULD HAVE MET
ANY AVATAR,
I'D HAVE TO PICK KYOSHI.
TAKING DOWN A SHARK SQUID
WITH ONE HAND?
NOW THAT'S A LADY
I'D LIKE TO GET TO KNOW.
- THIEVES!
GET BACK HERE!
- OH, DON'T WORRY.
THE AVATAR'S RIGHT HERE.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
GO GET 'EM!
- HAND OVER THE BAGS OR ELSE.
AH!
UGH!
[moaning]
- YOU SURE SHE'S THE AVATAR?
- [gasps]
[wind howls]
- EVERYONE, COME HERE!
IT'S THE AVATAR!
- YOU SURE?
I DON'T SENSE
ANY RAAVA ENERGY AROUND HER.
BESIDES, SHE'S NOT DRESSED
LIKE THE AVATAR.
DOESN'T THE AVATAR
HAVE PONYTAILS?
- DO YOU MIND?
I'M TRYING TO CONCENTRATE HERE.
AND, YES, I AM THE AVATAR.
I'M JUST
WEARING DIFFERENT CLOTHES
AND I CUT MY HAIR.
- SEE?
I TOLD YOU GUYS IT WAS HER.
HOW COME YOU'VE BEEN
AWAY SO LONG?
- I WAS HURT PRETTY BAD
AWHILE AGO,
AND LOST TOUCH
WITH MY AVATAR SPIRIT.
- NO WONDER I COULDN'T FEEL
RAAVA'S ENERGY.
- I CAME TO THE TREE OF TIME
HOPING TO RECONNECT WITH RAAVA
AND TURN ON
THE AVATAR STATE AGAIN.
BUT IT'S NOT WORKING.
THE LAST TIME I WAS HERE
I SAW ALL SORTS OF VISIONS.
NOW I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
- MAYBE WE CAN HELP YOU
GET BETTER.
- I'M SORRY, BUT FOR YEARS
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN SAYING
THEY CAN HELP ME
GET BETTER.
NOTHING'S WORKED.
I NEED TO FIGURE THIS OUT
ON MY OWN.
"DEAR MOM AND DAD,
"I ARRIVED IN REPUBLIC CITY
A COUPLE WEEKS AGO
"AND COULDN'T BE HAPPIER.
"IT'S NICE TO BE BACK
AT THE TEMPLE,
"AND IT'S GREAT
TO SEE MY FRIENDS AGAIN.
"DON'T WORRY,
I'M TAKING IT EASY,
"BUT HOPEFULLY
I'LL BE BACK IN ACTION SOON.
"I MISS YOU BOTH VERY MUCH.
"PLEASE GIVE NAGA
A BIG HUG FOR ME.
LOVE, KORRA."
RAAVA?
RAAVA!
I AM ENDING THIS.
[bell clangs]
[cheers and applause]
- [groaning]
[cheering]
- EXCUSE ME, WHO DO I TALK TO
ABOUT GETTING IN THE RING?
- [groaning]
IS THAT ALL YOU GOT?
[groaning]
- WE HAVE A WINNER!
[bell clangs]
- HURRY UP IN THERE!
- [barking]
- WHY DID YOU BRING ME
TO THE SWAMP?
- [barks]
- WAIT, I MET YOU
AT THE TREE OF TIME.
YOU SHOULD HAVE TOLD ME
WHO YOU WERE.
- IF I DID,
WOULD YOU HAVE FOLLOWED ME?
- I GET YOUR POINT.
BUT WHY DID YOU BRING ME HERE?
WHAT AM I GONNA FIND
IN THE SWAMP?
- NOT A WHAT.
A WHO.
- NO, WAIT!
COME BACK!
[panting]
YOU'RE JUST IN MY MIND.
YOU'RE NOT REAL.
[yelling]
AH!
UGH!
AHH!
[grunting]
AH!
[yelling]
[struggling]
HELP!
[exhales]
- FEELING BETTER?
- WHERE AM I?
WHAT HAPPENED?
- I WAS HOPING
YOU COULD TELL ME.
I FOUND YOU
PASSED OUT IN THE MUD.
- HOW DID YOU KNOW
I WAS OUT THERE?
- I'M PRETTY TAPPED INTO
THE GOINGS-ON AROUND HERE.
WHAT BRINGS YOU
TO THE SWAMP, ANYWAY?
- A SPIRIT LED ME HERE
AND TOLD ME
I WAS SUPPOSED TO FIND SOMEONE.
IS THAT YOU?
- BEATS ME.
BUT IF YOUR AVATAR SENSES
CALLED YOU HERE,
YOU SHOULD PROBABLY
LISTEN TO THEM.
- WAIT, YOU RECOGNIZE ME?
- IN A MANNER OF SPEAKING.
WE WERE GOOD FRIENDS
IN YOUR PREVIOUS LIFE.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
TOPH?
- [chuckles]
- NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
TWINKLETOES.