Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can master
all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
After Korra failed
to return to Republic city,
everyone's been worried
about her fate.
So Tenzin tasked Jinora, Ikki, and
Meelo with finding the Avatar.
Unbeknownst to the kids, Korra found
refuge in the swamp with Toph,
who discovered there was still
metal poison in her body.
But when Toph tried removing it,
Korra resisted.
Will the airbender kids find the
Avatar and help her return to action?
Tenzin, are you sure
you can't go with them?
Raiko asked me to stay here and help
figure out a diplomatic solution
to this Kuvira problem.
Mom, we'll be fine.
Grandpa Aang and his friends were around
our age when they traveled the world.
Well, at least I won't have to worry
about you starving out there.
Mom, we're going
to be in the wild,
living off the land.
We don't need your food.
But I made your favorite treat.
Sweet buns
with happy faces on them?
Well, I guess we're not
officially on the road yet.
Aw, this one is smudged.
I can't eat this.
You know, sometimes,
things get smudged in the wild.
Were you able to get
a read on Korra yet?
No, but once we're further out, I'll be
able to hone in on her spiritual energy.
We should be able to find her
within a few days.
Good luck, and be careful.
Remember, Jinora's in charge.
I answer to no man
or girl,
even if she does have tattoos.
Meelo.
Now, let's move out, soldiers.
Pepper, yip yip.
Finally!
I've been holding my pee
for an hour.
If you get through to Korra,
tell her I said hi.
Do you feel anything yet?
What's taking so long?
Ikki, I can't concentrate
if you keep talking.
Why don't you go play
with one of those spirits?
Jinora's spirity powers
are broken,
and she doesn't know
where Korra is.
My powers are not broken.
I just need
more than two seconds
and some quiet.
While you try to pull
yourself together,
Poki and I are going to go into town
and find out if anyone's seen Korra.
Sounds like a good plan to me.
Enough chitchat.
You can hold
the picture of Korra I drew.
Wow.
I didn't know you could draw.
You don't know a lot of things
about me, sister.
Let's roll.
Have you seen this woman?
Well, aren't you
an adorable little thing?
I'm not adorable.
I'm dangerous.
Dangerously cute
with those cheeks.
Aww.
This never happened.
Let's split.
The Avatar?
We still have one of those?
Haven't seen her, kid. Sorry.
Man!
- Can I trust you?
- I guess so.
I'm on a top secret mission
to find the Avatar.
Have you seen her?
I haven't, sorry.
Top secret mission, huh?
Yeah, it's been pretty dangerous.
I've seen some things.
Really? What kind of things?
Crazy things.
Cool.
I'm Meelo. What should I call
you, other than beautiful?
I'm Tuyen. Nice to meet you.
Ooh! Meelo found a girlfriend.
Go away, Ikki!
Jinora's been looking for you.
We're moving on.
Looks like you got to get back
to your mission.
Good luck, Meelo.
Thanks a lot, Ikki.
You drove away
the love of my life!
Jinora, Ikki!
It's Korra!
Where, where, where, where,
where, where, where?
It's just a photo of Korra.
At least it's something.
Pretty neat, huh?
She came by here
about six months ago.
Looks like someone just drummed
up a good old-fashioned lead.
Then where did she go?
Oh, I don't know, but she
wasn't looking too good.
Ikki, this is all your fault.
What? I didn't do anything.
Exactly, you need to start
pulling your weight.
That goes for you too,
so-called leader.
Remember when he used to be
so nice and sweet?
No.
So...
What's the plan for today?
You're looking at it.
But we didn't do anything
yesterday or the day before that.
I know!
Tell me the story about how
you taught Aang to earthbend.
What's there to tell?
I threw some rocks at the Avatar, he got
all whiny, and Sokka fell in a hole.
I thought
there'd be more to it than that.
What about the time you guys took down
the Firelord? That must have been epic.
Oh, yeah.
It was hot, I was on a blimp,
and I think a giant turtle showed up.
Wow, what a day.
Okay, you're terrible
at telling stories.
You're terrible
at listening to them.
Quit making all that racket.
If you're so antsy
to do something,
why don't you go and collect
some mushrooms for dinner?
You got it.
Take the path till you see
the boulder with a hole in it.
Then go to your left.
Oh, and make sure you get
the big, slimy ones.
They're the tastiest.
Hey, where's all the food
mom gave us?
I threw it in the river.
You did what?
That food was
supposed to last us two weeks.
Hey, keep it down!
I'm trying to meditate.
Yeah, keep it down, Ikki.
Meelo threw away all our food!
From now on,
we hunt for our meals.
Meelo, we're vegetarians.
We don't hunt.
Enough whining.
Poki and I will go
find some grub.
My name's Meelo.
I like to throw away food and
fart at inappropriate moments.
I'm Jinora. I'm so above it all
because I'm meditating all the time.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't see you there.
Wait!
You dropped your breakfast!
Hey.
Does this mean we're friends?
You're trespassing.
Hold it right there.
All right, little airbender.
Tell us what you're doing
in the Earth Empire.
Are you spying?
No. I swear I'm not a spy.
I've been traveling
with my brother and sister.
It's our first big mission, and my
dad, Tenzin, is counting on us.
But if we don't find the Avatar, he's
going to be really disappointed.
Can I talk to you for a second?
This girl is Tenzin's kid,
and she's looking
for the Avatar.
Do you know what that means?
No, but try this macaroon.
Get that out of my face!
Look, if we capture
these three airbender kids
and bring them to Kuvira,
I bet we'd get
a big-time promotion.
You mean
we'd get out of this dump?
Sorry, little lady.
It looks like we got off
on the wrong foot.
So you're out here
with your brother and sister.
Where's your campsite?
Why do you want to know?
We just want to get
the family back together again.
Maybe we could sit everybody down
and have a nice plate of macaroons.
Where did you get those?
I found a whole sack of food
down by the river,
and with each delicious snack
comes a lovely,
handwritten note.
This one says,
"you're my handsome little man."
That is so touching.
My mom wrote those notes.
That's our sack of food!
Enough with the cute notes!
Where are your brother
and sister?
Who cares?
I don't want to see them.
I'd rather hang out here
with you guys.
Hit me with one
of those macaroons.
Are you okay?
Yup, totally fine.
I hope you're hungry,
'cause we found some...
We found some berries.
Ugh.
Looks like you got
some bad berries.
So much for living off the land.
They're fine.
I just ate too many of
them because they're so...
so delicious.
Did you run into Ikki while you were
picking your poisonous berries?
Uh, no.
What, did she run off
or something?
I think so.
Great, now I got to go
find the Avatar and her.
This mission is getting worse
by the day.
This isn't only
your mission, Meelo.
I thought we were doing this
as a family.
It seems pretty lonely out here.
Where is everybody else?
I don't want to talk about it.
Aww, he's just upset because Kuvira's
taking all the troops to Zaofu,
and we had to stay here.
Well, it's the last city left, and
then the whole empire will be united.
And you know there's gonna be
a huge party afterwards.
It's tough to be left out, huh?
I know exactly
what you're going through.
- You do?
- Yeah.
My brother and sister are always
leaving me out of fun stuff.
I mean, we're supposed to be
looking for the Avatar together,
but they won't even let me help.
Well, that's not fair.
Maybe we can help you out.
So where have you
looked for her?
We've been traveling
down the west coast,
and the only lead we have is some guy
who said he saw her six months ago.
Well, we have troops
pretty much everywhere.
If anyone saw her,
they would have reported it.
What about this place?
Oh, that's the swamp.
No one goes there.
Don't get discouraged, Ikki.
You're a valuable member of the
team, and you have a big heart.
I know you're gonna find her.
Now, let's get you
out of those ropes.
You're welcome, Ikki.
Why did you do that?
We're saving you. Let's go.
I had everything under control.
I just found our food, and I
have an idea where Korra is.
You do? Then let's get going.
Hold on.
Sorry my brother and sister
knocked you out.
Nice chatting with you.
Macaroon.
There you are.
You got my dinner yet?
No, this swamp,
it did crazy things to my mind.
I had visions of all the
times my enemies hurt me.
Yeah, I figured something
like that might happen.
What?
You wanted me
to see those visions?
You are one twisted old lady,
you know that?
Look, I know you want
to get better,
and so does the swamp.
It can sense
you're out of balance.
It'll teach you
what you need to learn,
if you're open to listening.
Okay, swamp. I'm all ears.
You said you saw
your past enemies.
Now, why do you think that is?
I don't know,
because they've made me and a
lot of other people suffer.
Sounds like you're carrying
around your former enemies,
the same way you're still carrying
around that metal poison.
You ever consider maybe you
could learn something from them?
Sounds like the swamp's
messing with your mind too.
My mind is just fine, thank you.
Listen, what did Amon want?
Equality for all.
Unalaq?
He brought back the spirits.
And Zaheer believed in freedom.
I guess.
The problem was, those guys
were totally out of balance,
and they took their ideologies too far.
Okay, fine.
But that doesn't explain
why they keep haunting me.
Because you need to face
your fears.
You can't expect to deal
with future enemies
if you're still fighting
the old ones.
Maybe you're right, but how
am I supposed to move on?
Boy, you avatars sure need
a lot of hand-holding.
Get up.
We're going
to the Banyangrove tree.
Those soldiers said
there weren't any troops here,
and I figure
if Korra's not feeling good,
she might come to a spiritual
place like this to get better.
There is an enormous amount of spiritual
activity here, but I don't feel Korra.
Well, that's what we get
for listening to Ikki.
Guys, we just got here.
Let's at least look around.
I'm sorry, Ikki,
but I'm with Meelo on this.
I don't think
we're going to find her here.
Let's go, pepper.
Aah!
Why did those stupid vines
pull us in here anyway?
Because they want us here.
I'm telling you,
Korra's got to be close.
I don't know, Ikki.
I still don't sense Korra.
Well, you haven't sensed her the entire
time we've been looking for her.
Next time I go on a mission,
it's going to be boys only,
just Poki and me.
It's beautiful.
The roots of the Banyangrove tree spread
out for miles in every direction,
connecting this whole swamp.
Your problem is you've been
disconnected for too long,
disconnected from the people
who love you
and disconnected from yourself.
I'm tired of listening to you!
Korra. I know where Korra is!
Yeah!
I can't believe it!
I saw Jinora, Ikki, and Meelo.
They're here!
Good.
Hopefully, they're here
to take you home.
Korra!
Oh, we missed you so much, Korra.
I missed you so much too.
How did you find me
all the way out here?
Jinora sensed your energy.
But we never would've been
here if it weren't for Ikki.
I never would've stormed off and found
those soldiers if it weren't for Meelo.
I was trying
to toughen up these ladies,
but I guess
it was a team effort.
I love your hair.
It's so you.
I-I'm so sorry.
This is Meelo, Jinora, and Ikki,
Aang and Katara's grandchildren.
Your grandpa was
a real pain in my butt.
Wait a minute,
cranky, old, blind...
You must be Toph!
Oh, I like this one.
You need to come home, Korra.
Kuvira is taking over
the Earth kingdom.
You have to stop her.
I don't know.
I'm not the Avatar I used to be.
I can't even go into the Avatar state.
Please, Korra.
The world needs you back.
All right, I'm ready.
I'm not bending it out of you.
You got to do this on your own.
Close your eyes.
Clear your mind.
And don't freak out
like last time.
Now, focus your energy.
Find the metal.
Let it move through your body.
That fight is over.
Release the fear.
Well done, Korra.
The Avatar is back in business!
I feel so much lighter.
Thank you so much
for helping me.
I'd like to give you a hug now
if that's okay with you.
All right. You earned it.
- Bye, Toph!
- Bye, see you later.
- It was so nice to meet you!
- We're gonna miss you!
Finally, some peace and quiet.