- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- AFTER THREE YEARS,
KUVIRA HAS UNITED
THE FORMER EARTH KINGDOM STATES
UNDER HER NEW
EARTH EMPIRE BANNER.
BUT ONE HOLDOUT REMAINS:
ZAOFU.
DURING THAT SAME TIME,
ASAMI REBUILT THE COMPANY
HER FATHER CREATED
AND HELPED REDESIGN
THE CITY'S INFRASTRUCTURE.
AND MOST RECENTLY, THE
AIRBENDER KIDS FOUND THE AVATAR.
KORRA RID HERSELF OF
THE RESIDUAL POISON IN HER BODY
AND IS READY TO RETURN
TO ACTION.
- WE HAVE AN EMERGENCY.
- I'LL CONTACT PRESIDENT RAIKO.
HE'LL SEND THE UNITED FORCES.
- CALL WHOMEVER YOU WANT, BUT
THEY'LL NEVER MAKE IT IN TIME.
KUVIRA'S ALREADY HERE,
AND SHE BROUGHT HER ENTIRE ARMY.
- BY THIS TIME TOMORROW,
MY MOTHER WILL HAVE SIGNED
OUR TREATY,
AND THE EARTH EMPIRE
WILL FINALLY BE UNITED.
- DON'T GET AHEAD OF YOURSELF.
SECURING YOUR HOMETOWN
WON'T BE LIKE EVERY OTHER CITY.
- ZAOFU STOPPED BEING MY HOME
LONG AGO.
I'M READY TO TAKE IT BY FORCE.
- NO.
THE EYES OF THE WORLD
ARE ON US NOW.
WE MUST DO THIS RIGHT.
THAT'S WHY WE NEED BOLIN.
- DO YOU REALLY THINK
WE CAN RELY ON HIM?
- SU TRUSTS HIM.
SHE'LL LISTEN TO HIM.
- ARE YOU SURE WE SHOULD BE
GOING TO ZAOFU?
DAD WANTED US TO BRING YOU
BACK TO REPUBLIC CITY.
- IF KUVIRA'S HEADING TO ZAOFU,
SO AM I.
SHE NEEDS TO KNOW
THAT THE AVATAR IS BACK.
THE WORLD NEEDS TO KNOW.
- WHOO-HOO!
AVATAR FIGHT!
THIS IS GOING TO BE AWESOME!
- MEELO,
THERE'S NOT GONNA BE A FIGHT.
KUVIRA SAVED MY DAD.
SHE WAS A CAPTAIN IN SU'S GUARD.
I THINK SHE CAN BE
REASONED WITH.
- WHAT?
NO FIGHT?
WHY DID WE GO THROUGH ALL
THAT TROUBLE TO SAVE YOU
IF YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
BEAT SOMEONE UP?
- ZHU LI,
IS THIS THING ON?
- WE'RE ROLLING, SIR.
- OKAY, I'M VARRICK OF VARRICK
INDUSTRIES INTERNATIONAL,
AND THIS IS
SPIRIT VINE EXPERIMENT 3-02
HAND ME THE THING.
[grunting]
IN THIS STASIS CAPSULE IS A
PRESERVED SPIRIT VINE SAMPLE
WEIGHING APPROXIMATELY
TWO ZHU LIS.
I HAVE POSTULATED
THAT THESE SPIRIT VINES
ARE A FORM OF PURE ENERGY
THAT'S UNSTABLE
IN WHAT WE CALL
"TYPICAL EARTH CONDITIONS."
THIS MACHINE SHOULD TRANSFER
THE ENERGY FROM THE VINE
INTO A BATTERY
USING ELECTRICAL CURRENTS,
REVERSE MAGNETIC POLARITY,
AND A LITTLE-KNOWN PHENOMENON
I CALL THE VARRI-EFFECT.
IT'S WORKING.
IT'S REGISTERING FIVE VARRICKS
OF POWER...
NOW SEVEN VARRICKS.
WHOA.
WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- OH!
- AHH!
ZHU LI,
SHUT IT DOWN.
THERE ARE TOO MANY VARRICKS.
AHH!
- AHH!
SIR...
- [grunting]
YOU'RE TOO HEAVY.
YOU KNOW, YOU COULD STAND
TO LOSE A FEW ZHU LIS.
- I THINK YOU'RE JUST WEAK, SIR.
PULL HARDER.
- [grunting]
both: AHH!
- VARRICK,
YOU SAVED ME.
- OF COURSE I SAVED YOU.
I CAN'T CLEAN THIS PLACE UP
BY MYSELF.
GRAB A BROOM.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
WERE WE ATTACKED?
- NO, WE WERE SPIRIT-VINED,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'M PUTTING THE KIBOSH
ON THIS PROJECT.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT.
DO YOU REALIZE WHAT WE CAN DO
WITH THIS KIND OF POWER?
- YES, I DO.
AND THAT'S WHY WE'VE GOT TO
PUT AN END TO IT.
WHAT IF IT FELL INTO
THE WRONG HANDS?
- SINCE WHEN DOES THAT MATTER
TO YOU?
- I KNOW.
IT'S NOT LIKE ME, RIGHT?
USUALLY,
I LOOK AT A PROJECT LIKE THIS,
AND ALL I THINK IS, "WOW, I CAN
MAKE A TON OF MONEY OFF THIS."
BUT RECENTLY, I'VE BEEN HAVING
THESE STRANGE FEELINGS INSIDE.
IT'S LIKE I'M...
CONCERNED WITH OTHERS.
AND THERE'S THIS NAGGING VOICE
IN MY HEAD
CONSTANTLY TELLING ME
WHAT'S RIGHT FROM WRONG.
- I BELIEVE THAT VOICE
IS YOUR CONSCIENCE, SIR.
- WELL, I'M THE OTHER VOICE
IN YOUR HEAD,
AND I'M TELLING YOU,
YOU WILL CONTINUE THIS PROJECT.
- SORRY, NO.
I JUST REALLY GOT TO STAND
MY GROUND ON THIS ONE.
WHOA!
- NOW THERE'S A VOICE IN MY HEAD
TELLING ME
TO DROP YOU ON THE TRACKS.
SHOULD I LISTEN?
- NO, NO.
HEAD VOICES ARE LIARS.
WHAT DO HEAD VOICES KNOW?
I'LL WORK ON THE PROJECT.
PLEASE DON'T DROP ME.
AHH!
- ASAMI, YOU CAME.
I'M HERE TO RETURN THESE.
- YOU NEVER OPENED THEM.
- STOP WRITING ME.
I NEVER WANT TO SEE
OR HEAR FROM YOU AGAIN.
- PLEASE,
JUST LET ME SAY ONE THING,
THEN I'LL NEVER CONTACT YOU
AGAIN.
I CAN'T FORGIVE MYSELF FOR ALL
THE HORRIBLE THINGS I'VE DONE,
AND I NEVER EXPECT YOU
TO FORGIVE ME.
I TORE OUR FAMILY APART
AND DESTROYED OUR GOOD NAME.
BUT IN A LIFE OF REGRET,
YOU'RE THE ONE THING I LOOK
BACK ON THAT MAKES ME SMILE.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
I'M SO PROUD OF YOU, ASAMI.
YOU ARE THE GREATEST THING
I EVER CREATED.
- AM I IN TROUBLE?
- NO.
IN FACT, I HAVE GOOD NEWS.
WE WANT YOU TO BE PART
OF OUR INNER CIRCLE.
- INNER CIRCLE! NO WAY! YES!
AHEM,
THAT IS A GREAT HONOR.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN,
EXACTLY?
- IT MEANS YOU'VE PROVEN
YOUR WORTH.
WE'RE SO CLOSE TO UNITING
THE EMPIRE,
BUT SU HAS SOME RESENTMENT
TOWARDS ME AND BAATAR
THAT MIGHT CLOUD HER JUDGMENT
AND STOP HER FROM MAKING
A WISE DECISION.
WE BELIEVE YOU CAN HELP HER
SEE CLEARLY.
- I CAN DO THAT.
BY THE TIME I'M FINISHED
TELLING HER
ALL THE GREAT THINGS WE'VE DONE,
SHE'LL BE BEGGING TO JOIN.
- GOOD,
BECAUSE WE'RE HERE.
- AREN'T ALL THESE TROOPS
GONNA SEND THE WRONG MESSAGE?
- THE ARMY IS HERE
TO PROJECT STRENGTH.
YOU'RE HERE TO PRESENT PEACE.
- OPAL,
YOU'RE HERE TOO.
- NO,
YOU'VE CHOSEN YOUR SIDE.
- SIDES?
THERE SHOULDN'T BE SIDES.
I KNOW, WHY DON'T WE ALL STAND
IN A CIRCLE, HUH,
MAYBE HOLD HANDS?
- I'M NOT GIVING UP ZAOFU.
I DON'T CARE IF YOU BROUGHT
YOUR ENTIRE ARMY.
- SU, I DIDN'T BRING MY ARMY
TO THREATEN YOU.
I WANTED TO SHOW YOU
ALL THAT YOUR SON AND I
HAVE ACCOMPLISHED.
- YOU MUST REALIZE
WHAT YOU'RE DOING
GOES AGAINST EVERYTHING YOUR
FATHER AND I TRIED TO TEACH YOU.
- SON, YOU BELONG HERE.
- WHY?
SO THAT I CAN GO ON LIVING
IN YOUR SHADOW?
- DON'T SAY THAT.
CAN'T YOU SEE
SHE'S BRAINWASHED YOU.
- HA,
I DIDN'T BRAINWASH HIM.
I SET HIM FREE.
AND NOW HE'S ACCOMPLISHED
MORE WITH ME
THAN HE EVER COULD HAVE
WITH YOU.
- OKAY, GUYS, OBVIOUSLY,
THERE'S A LOT OF PERSONAL,
PAINFUL HISTORY HERE.
SO WHAT DO SAY WE JUST ALL
FORGET ABOUT THAT STUFF, HUH?
I MEAN,
THAT'S THE PAST.
RIGHT, WING?
RIGHT, WEI?
YOU GUYS KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
HIGH FIVE.
ALL RIGHT.
NO, IT'S COOL.
YOU KNOW WHAT I THINK
WE NEED TO DO?
FOCUS ON THE FUTURE.
AND THE FUTURE IS BRIGHT.
LET ME TELL YOU.
I'VE SEEN IT.
YEAH, SAW IT LAST MONTH.
WE WENT TO THIS TOWN
THAT HAD NOTHING.
MOST OF THE PEOPLE THERE
HAD NEVER EVEN SEEN
A SATOMOBILE BEFORE.
BUT NOW THEY HAVE
TWO SATOMOBILES,
RUNNING WATER,
AND A MAGNET TRAIN
THAT GOES RIGHT THROUGH
THEIR TOWN.
I MEAN,
HOW AWESOME IS THAT?
- THEY MIGHT HAVE BEEN HAPPY
WHEN YOU FIRST ARRIVED,
BUT I'VE SEEN WHAT HAPPENS
AFTER YOU LEAVE.
CITIZENS ARE FORCED TO WORK
AS SLAVE LABOR.
DISSENTERS ARE SENT OFF
TO WHO KNOWS WHERE.
- YOU'RE WRONG, OPAL.
NOW, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU THINK YOU'VE SEEN,
BUT I'M GIVING YOU
THE 100% BOLIN GUARANTEE
THAT WE'RE MAKING
THE EARTH EMPIRE
A BETTER PLACE TO LIVE.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU BROUGHT BOLIN HERE
TO TRY TO SWAY US.
LEAVE.
ZAOFU WILL NEVER ACCEPT YOU
AS THEIR LEADER.
- THEN YOU LEAVE ME NO CHOICE.
YOU HAVE 24 HOURS TO AGREE
TO JOIN THE EMPIRE,
OR WE TAKE THE CITY BY FORCE.
- I SEE IT.
ZAOFU.
WE MADE IT.
AND A BUNCH OF OTHER PEOPLE
ARE HERE TOO.
- OH, NO.
I HOPE WE'RE NOT TOO LATE.
- KORRA?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
YOU DISAPPEARED.
EVERYONE WAS SO WORRIED.
, I'LL TELL YOU THE WHOLE STORY
LATER.
RIGHT NOW,
I WANT TO HELP YOU STOP KUVIRA.
WHAT CAN I DO?
- YOU WERE JUST BLUFFING, RIGHT?
I MEAN, YOU'RE NOT REALLY
GOING TO ATTACK ZAOFU...ARE YOU?
- WHEN PEOPLE DON'T COOPERATE,
WE MUST FIND OTHER WAYS
OF CONVINCING THEM TO JOIN.
- OTHER WAYS?
HOW MANY TIMES HAVE WE USED
THESE OTHER WAYS
IN THE PAST?
- IT'S NOT FOR YOU
TO WORRY ABOUT.
- SO...
WHAT DOES HAPPEN
TO ALL OF THOSE TOWNS
AND VILLAGES AFTER WE LEAVE?
I JUST REALIZED
I'VE NEVER REALLY GONE BACK
AND CHECKED ON THEM.
- THOSE PEOPLE
ARE MY LOYAL SUBJECTS,
AND THEY CONTRIBUTE
TO THE EMPIRE HOWEVER I SEE FIT.
NOW THAT YOU'RE IN
THE INNER CIRCLE,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO ACCEPT
SOME HARD TRUTHS.
- MAYBE I'M NOT REALLY
AN INNER-CIRCLE KIND OF GUY.
OR--OR MAYBE
WE DON'T TAKE OVER ZAOFU.
WE COULD JUST LET THEM BE
ON THEIR OWN,
THEN YAY,
THE EMPIRE'S UNITED.
CONGRATULATIONS TO US.
- I DIDN'T KNOW
YOUR PERSONAL FEELINGS FOR OPAL
WERE STRONGER THAN
YOUR LOYALTY TO ME.
ZAOFU WILL JOIN US.
THE ONLY THING
I'M SECOND-GUESSING
IS THE DECISION
TO BRING YOU ALONG.
MAYBE YOU NEED TO SPEND
SOME TIME IN A REEDUCATION CAMP.
- I THOUGHT THAT'S WHERE
WE SEND PEOPLE
TO LEARN NEW TRADE SKILLS.
- HARD TRUTHS, BOLIN.
- YOUR LOYALTY
SEEMS TO BE WAVERING.
- NO, NO,
I'M TOTALLY ON YOUR SIDE,
COMPLETELY 100% LOYAL.
- HOW DID THINGS GET SO BAD
BETWEEN YOU AND KUVIRA?
I THOUGHT SHE WAS YOUR PROTEGE?
- SHE WAS MORE THAN THAT.
SHE WAS LIKE A DAUGHTER TO ME.
I TOOK HER IN
WHEN SHE WAS EIGHT YEARS OLD
AND NOURISHED HER TALENTS.
KUVIRA WAS SMART,
A NATURAL LEADER,
AND QUICKLY ROSE
THROUGH THE RANKS.
I SAW MYSELF IN HER.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
- THREE YEARS AGO, AFTER
THE FALL OF THE EARTH QUEEN,
RAIKO AND TENZIN
CAME TO SEE ME.
- THE EARTH KINGDOM IS IN CHAOS.
THERE'S A VACUUM OF POWER,
AND I'M CONCERNED ABOUT
WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IF SOMEONE DOESN'T TAKE CONTROL
OF THE SITUATION.
- AND DO YOU THINK I SHOULD BE
THE ONE?
- YOU'RE THE PERFECT PERSON
TO TAKE CHARGE.
THE WORLD LEADERS TRUST YOU,
AND AS A BEIFONG,
YOU HAVE CREDIBILITY
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM.
- I'M HONORED
THAT YOU THOUGHT OF ME,
BUT I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN IMPOSING MY IDEALS
ON AN ENTIRE NATION.
I'M AFRAID I CAN'T HELP YOU.
- SUYIN,
I KNOW THIS ISN'T MY PLACE,
BUT I THINK YOU SHOULD DO THIS.
ZAOFU HAS ALWAYS BEEN A BEACON
OF MODERN PROGRESS,
AND NOW YOU CAN SHARE THAT
WITH EVERYONE.
- WHAT WOULD YOU HAVE ME DO,
MARCH INTO BA SING
SE WITH AN ARMY?
WE'D BE SEEN AS CONQUERORS
AND GREETED WITH NOTHING
BUT WAR.
- THERE ARE ALREADY WARS.
THE EARTH QUEEN NEARLY DESTROYED
OUR NATION.
THIS IS OUR OPPORTUNITY
TO CHANGE THINGS.
- IT'S NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
I DIDN'T REALIZE AT THE TIME,
BUT THAT MOMENT CREATED A RIFT
BETWEEN US.
KUVIRA TURNED MY OWN SON
AGAINST ME.
AND TOGETHER THEY PLOTTED
BEHIND MY BACK.
WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?
- WE'RE DOING WHAT YOU
DON'T HAVE THE GUTS TO DO.
WE'RE GOING TO BA SING SE
TO HELP BRING ORDER BACK
TO THE EARTH KINGDOM.
- NO.
YOU WILL STAY HERE.
- AND WHO'S GOING TO STOP ME?
YOUR SECURITY FORCE
WAS MORE THAN HAPPY
TO JOIN MY CAUSE.
THEY'RE SOME OF
THE BEST FIGHTERS IN THE WORLD,
AND THEY ARE TIRED
OF BEING TREATED
LIKE EXOTIC BIRDS IN YOUR CAGE.
- IF YOU LEAVE NOW,
YOU WILL NEVER BE WELCOMED BACK.
- WHEN I CHOOSE TO RETURN,
IT WILL BE ON MY OWN TERMS.
- KUVIRA AND BAATAR LEFT
THAT DAY WITH VARRICK,
MY SECURITY FORCE, AND A FEW
OF ZAOFU'S WEALTHIEST CITIZENS.
AFTER KUVIRA PROVED HERSELF
BY STABILIZING BA SING SE,
RAIKO AND THE OTHER WORLD
LEADERS MADE HER
THE PROVISIONAL HEAD
OF THE EARTH KINGDOM.
ONCE SHE REFUSED TO STEP DOWN,
I KNEW IT WAS ONLY
A MATTER OF TIME
UNTIL SHE MADE HER WAY
BACK HERE.
- I WANT TO FIX THIS.
- YOU CAN.
GO INTO THE AVATAR STATE
AND DEMOLISH HER ARMY.
REMOVE KUVIRA FROM POWER
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
- FIGHTING IS SOMETHING
THE OLD ME WOULD DO,
BUT THAT ALWAYS
MADE THINGS WORSE.
LET ME TALK WITH KUVIRA.
MAYBE I CAN REASON WITH HER.
- KUVIRA DOESN'T LISTEN
TO REASON.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE KUVIRA
LOCKED ME IN HERE
LIKE A PRISONER.
I'M NOT FEELING WELL.
I THINK I'M RUNNING OUT OF AIR.
ZHU LI,
HOLD YOUR BREATH.
- I'M NOT HOLDING MY BREATH.
- GREAT.
NOW WE'RE BOTH GONNA DIE.
- VARRICK.
VARRICK.
- AUGH,
AND THE HEAD VOICES ARE BACK.
BOLIN,
THANK GOODNESS YOU'RE HERE.
WHERE DID THAT HATCH COME FROM?
FORGET THE HATCH.
THERE'S SOMETHING IMPORTANT
I'VE GOT TO TELL YOU.
- WELL,
THERE'S SOMETHING IMPORTANT
I'VE GOT TELL YOU TOO.
both:
KUVIRA'S CRAZY.
- HOW'D YOU FIND OUT?
- WHEN I REFUSED TO BUILD HER
A SUPER WEAPON,
SHE THREATENED MY LIFE.
- SHE THREATENED ME TOO,
AND SHE'S THREATENING ZAOFU.
AND IT TURNS OUT
SHE'S BEEN THREATENING VILLAGES
THIS WHOLE TIME.
WE'VE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE.
- I COULDN'T AGREE MORE, KID.
- WE HAVE AN UNEXPECTED GUEST.
THE AVATAR IS HERE TO SEE YOU.
- KORRA, IT'S SUCH AN HONOR
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
THE LAST I HEARD, YOU WERE
STILL HEALING IN THE SOUTH POLE.
- WELL,
I'M FEELING MUCH BETTER NOW.
- THAT'S WONDERFUL NEWS.
- I'M HERE TO ASK YOU
TO BACK DOWN.
PLEASE,
TAKE YOUR ARMY AND LEAVE.
- I THINK WE BOTH KNOW
THAT'S NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
- I CAN'T LET YOU TAKE ZAOFU.
- LOOK, I WAS TASKED
WITH BRINGING STABILITY
TO THE EARTH KINGDOM.
ZAOFU IS THE LAST HOLDOUT.
WHY SHOULD I TREAT IT
DIFFERENTLY
THAN ANY OTHER STATE?
- WHAT YOU'RE DOING ISN'T RIGHT.
- I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE JUST
TRYING TO DO SU A FAVOR,
BUT YOU CAN'T COME TO ME
AS I'M ON THE VERGE
OF REUNITING MY NATION
AND TELL ME TO STOP.
THE WORLD WAS DESCENDING
INTO CHAOS WHILE YOU WERE GONE.
IN ORDER TO FIX IT, I HAD
TO MAKE SOME TOUGH DECISIONS.
- I KNOW WHAT THAT'S LIKE.
I'VE HAD PLENTY OF PEOPLE
MAD AT ME
ABOUT DECISIONS I'VE MADE.
- EXACTLY.
KORRA,
IF YOU REALLY WANT TO HELP,
GO BACK TO SU AND TRY TO TALK
SOME SENSE INTO HER.
LET'S CALL A TEMPORARY TRUCE.
I WON'T MAKE ANY MOVES
UNTIL YOU TALK TO HER
AND GET BACK TO ME.
- MAYBE THAT WILL BE
FOR THE BEST.
- HAVE YOU SEEN BOLIN?
- HE CAME BY TO SEE VARRICK,
BUT WE TURNED HIM AWAY.
- OPEN THE DOOR.
WE HAVE SOME FUGITIVES TO CATCH.
- OKAY, I SAY WE GO UP
AND AROUND THE MOUNTAINS
AND SNEAK INTO ZAOFU
FROM THE REAR.
- WE'RE NOT GOING TO ZAOFU.
THAT PLACE IS DOOMED.
WE'VE GOT TO HEAD
TO REPUBLIC CITY.
- WHAT? NO. NO, NO, NO.
WE'VE GOT TO HELP HERE.
- WE'LL BE HELPING
BY WARNING THE WORLD
ABOUT KUVIRA'S POTENTIAL
SUPER WEAPON.
- WELL,
THAT IS HELPING,
BUT IT'S A COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT TYPE OF HELPING.
HMM, LET ME THINK ABOUT THIS.
AHH!
- ARGH!
- AHH!
AHH! AHH!
THAT'S NOT THE FLAMETHROWER.
WHAT IDIOT DESIGNED
THESE THINGS?
- YOU DID, SIR.
- LESS LECTURING,
MORE SAVING MY LIFE.
- UGH!
AHH!
ARGH!
- OH!
- ARGH!
- AHH!
UGH.
AHH!
ARGH!
- HEY,
I THINK I FIGURED IT OUT.
- AHH!
SIR, YOU'RE MAKING THIS
VERY DIFFICULT.
AHH!
- ARGH!
YAH!
- AUGH!
- AHH!
- ARGH!
ARGH!
- AUGH!
AHH!
- AHH!
AHH-AHH!
ARGH!
- STOP.
TURN YOURSELF OVER OR ELSE.
- THANKS A LOT, ZHU LI.
- YOU CAME BACK.
- WHEN I FIRST CAME HERE,
IT WAS BECAUSE I WANTED
TO TELL YOU FACE-TO-FACE
THAT I NEVER WANTED TO SEE
OR HEAR FROM YOU AGAIN.
I WANTED MY WORDS TO HURT YOU,
SO THAT YOU WOULD KNOW
HOW YOU HURT ME.
- I'M SORRY.
- BUT WHEN I SAW YOU,
IT WASN'T ANGER I FELT.
IT WAS SADNESS.
YOU TAINTED OUR PAST AND
DESTROYED OUR FUTURE TOGETHER.
- I WANT TO MAKE AMENDS.
- I'M NOT SURE I'LL EVER BE ABLE
TO FORGIVE YOU,
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN
I SHOULDN'T TRY.
I THOUGHT WE COULD PLAY
SOME PAI SHO,
LIKE WE USED TO.
- NOTHING WOULD MAKE ME HAPPIER.
[together]
AUGH!
- DON'T TORTURE US.
- SEND THESE THREE AWAY
ON THE NEXT TRAIN.
BOLIN AND ZHU LI WILL BE GOING
TO THE REEDUCATION CAMP
FOR OUR MOST SEVERE DISSENTERS.
AND YOU WILL CONTINUE WORK
ON THE SPIRIT ENERGY PROJECT
UNDER CLOSE,
ARMED SUPERVISION.
I WANT IT WEAPONIZED
IMMEDIATELY.
- PLEASE,
HAVE MERCY ON ME.
DON'T SEND ME AWAY.
TAKE ME BACK.
- WHY WOULD I?
- BECAUSE MY ONLY MISTAKE WAS
BEING LOYAL TO THE WRONG PERSON.
I WAS BLINDLY DEVOTED
TO VARRICK,
AND I LOOKED PAST ALL THE TIMES
HE RIDICULED ME
OR ORDERED ME AROUND OR MADE ME
CLEAN HIS DISGUSTING FEET,
BECAUSE I THOUGHT HE POSSESSED
THE MOST BRILLIANT MIND
IN THE WORLD,
BUT WHEN I MET YOU,
I REALIZED I WAS WRONG.
COMPARED TO YOU,
VARRICK'S A FOOL.
- HEY, COME ON.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
- I BELIEVE IN EVERYTHING
YOU'VE DONE,
AND I BELIEVE IN YOUR VISION.
I WANT TO DEVOTE MY LIFE TO YOU.
I PLEDGE MY ALLEGIANCE TO YOU,
GREAT UNITER.
- YOU TWO COULD LEARN SOMETHING
FROM HER.
RISE, ZHU LI.
I'LL GIVE YOU ANOTHER CHANCE.
- THINK ABOUT WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
WE'RE PARTNERS.
WE HAVE HISTORY.
- I DID EVERYTHING
YOU EVER ASKED OF ME,
AND YOU NEVER APPRECIATED IT.
GUARDS, DO THE THING.
- NO,
NOT THE THING.
ZHU LI.
- WHERE'S SU?
I HAVE TO TALK TO HER.
- SHE'S NOT HERE.
SHE TOOK WING AND WEI.
THEY'RE GOING TO SNEAK INTO
KUVIRA'S CAMP
AND PUT AN END TO THIS.
- NO.