- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- KUVIRA HAS DEFEATED THE AVATAR
AND NOW CONTROLS
THE ENTIRE EARTH EMPIRE.
LUCKILY, THE AIRBENDER KIDS
AND OPAL RESCUED KORRA
AND ESCAPED ZAOFU.
FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN THREE YEARS,
KORRA WILL FINALLY BE BACK
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
MEANWHILE, VARRICK AND BOLIN
ESCAPED FROM BAATAR JR.
AND ARE ON THE RUN.
BUT WILL THEY MAKE IT
BACK TO THE CITY IN TIME
TO WARN EVERYONE ABOUT KUVIRA'S
NEW SPIRIT ENERGY SUPER WEAPON?
[squeaking]
[groaning]
- NAGA!
I MISSED YOU SO MUCH, GIRL.
- MOM! DAD!
WE'RE BACK!
AND WE GOT KORRA!
- WELL, AREN'T YOU A SIGHT
FOR SORE EYES.
BUM-JU AND I SURE MISSED YOU.
- IT'S SO GREAT TO SEE YOU
AGAIN, BUMI.
AND YOU TOO, BUM-JU.
[Bum-ju screeches]
- WELL DONE, KIDS.
I'M PROUD OF YOU ALL
FOR FINDING KORRA.
- PROUD ENOUGH
TO GET ME MY TATS?
- NO.
WELCOME HOME.
- I MISSED YOU, TENZIN.
- NOW, I HATE TO GET RIGHT DOWN
TO BUSINESS,
BUT I WANT TO HEAR WHAT HAPPENED
IN ZAOFU.
[Bum-ju squeaks]
- WAY TO RUIN THE MOMENT.
- KUVIRA'S WHOLE ARMY WAS THERE.
SHE CAPTURED MOM, DAD,
AND MY BROTHERS.
- I THOUGHT I WAS STRONG ENOUGH
TO STOP HER.
I FEEL LIKE SUCH A FAILURE.
- NO ONE EXPECTED YOU
TO HANDLE KUVIRA ON YOUR OWN.
IT'S UP TO ALL OF US
TO FIND A WAY TO DEAL WITH HER.
WE'RE JUST GLAD
TO HAVE YOU BACK.
- WHERE'S BOLIN?
HE'S NOT STILL ON KUVIRA'S SIDE,
IS HE?
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
HE WOULD STAY WITH HER
AFTER WHAT SHE DID TO MY FAMILY.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS.
- [panting]
HOW ABOUT YOU USE YOUR OWN LEGS
FOR A WHILE?
- YOU KNOW, WHEN I FLED
REPUBLIC CITY WITH ZHU LI,
SHE CARRIED ME TWENTY MILES
IN ONE DAY.
AND THAT WAS AFTER
SHE SPRAINED HER ANKLE.
- WELL, ZHU LI'S NOT HERE,
OKAY?
- THAT'S FINE.
LEAVE ME HERE.
LET THE WORMS GOBBLE ME UP.
I DESERVE IT.
- NO WAY, MISTER.
YOU'RE NOT GETTING OFF
THAT EASILY.
YOU'RE RESPONSIBLE FOR THAT
WEAPON KUVIRA'S TRYING TO MAKE.
WHICH, MAY I REMIND YOU,
COULD HURT A LOT OF PEOPLE.
- NO, DON'T REMIND ME!
I KNOW, I'M A HORRIBLE,
HORRIBLE PERSON.
- OKAY, LOOK,
KUVIRA FOOLED US BOTH
INTO DOING HER DIRTY WORK
AND I'M NOT HAPPY ABOUT IT
EITHER.
BUT YOU KNOW HOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE IT UP TO THE WORLD?
BY GETTING BACK TO REPUBLIC CITY
AND WARNING EVERYONE
WHAT SHE'S UP TO.
SO I WANT YOU TO TAKE MY HAND,
AND MARCH WITH ME
OUT OF THIS FOREST!
- YOU REALLY HAVE A WAY
WITH WORDS, KID.
NO WONDER I MADE YOU
A MOVER STAR.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL TAKE
THE DRIVER'S SEAT FOR A WHILE.
HOP ON.
- [sighs]
GREAT.
MY FEET COULD USE A BREAK.
- [straining]
OKAY. OH, BOY.
HERE WE GO.
[groaning]
- AH!
- OH!
- ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
- I HOPE YOU HAVEN'T BEEN
WAITING LONG.
- ONLY THREE YEARS.
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
- YOU TOO.
- AND I'M LOVING THE HAIR.
- THANKS.
YOU'RE LOOKING SNAZZY AS ALWAYS.
- COME ON, MAKO GOT US
A TABLE AT THE RESTAURANT.
- KORRA!
- HI, MAKO.
- HELLO THERE,
PRINCE WU,
RIGHTFUL HEIR TO THE THRONE,
AND THIS GUY'S BOSS.
[chuckles] I BET HE'S TOLD YOU
A LOT ABOUT ME.
- NOPE.
NOT A THING.
- THEN WE HAVE SO MUCH
TO TALK ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING TO LOVE
THE FOOD HERE.
I KNOW THE CHEF PERSONALLY.
LET'S START WITH A ROUND
OF YOUR SPICY OCTOPUS FRITTERS.
AND KEEP THE CUCUMBER-ALOE WATER
FLOWING.
GOT TO KEEP THIS PRINCELY SKIN
HYDRATED.
- I THOUGHT IT WAS JUST
GOING TO BE THE THREE OF US.
- SORRY,
I COULDN'T DITCH HIM.
BUT HE PROMISED TO BE ON
HIS BEST BEHAVIOR.
- HEY, POP INTO THE AVATAR STATE
FOR ME.
I WANT TO SEE YOUR EYES GLOW.
- WHAT?
NO.
- [moans]
- SO CAN YOU GO INTO THE AVATAR
STATE AGAIN?
I WAS WORRIED WHEN YOU TOLD ME
YOU COULDN'T.
- WAIT.
WHEN DID SHE TELL YOU
SHE COULDN'T?
[straw slurping]
WHAT'S GOING ON WITH YOU TWO?
- I WROTE TO ASAMI
WHILE I WAS AWAY.
I ASKED HER NOT TO TELL YOU.
I'M SORRY.
- WELL, WHY DIDN'T YOU EVER
WRITE TO ME?
OR BOLIN?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
- A "HELLO" WOULD HAVE BEEN
NICE.
- MAKO, IF IT MAKES YOU
FEEL ANY BETTER,
SHE DIDN'T WRITE ME EITHER.
- WHY WOULD SHE...
[sighs]
NEVER MIND.
- I'M SORRY I DIDN'T STAY
IN TOUCH, BUT I'M BACK NOW.
AND I WANT TO KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT WHAT'S BEEN GOING ON
WITH YOU TWO.
- WELL, I KIND OF HAVE
SOME BIG NEWS.
I WENT TO VISIT MY FATHER
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
HE'D BEEN WRITING ME LETTERS
AND I GUESS I FINALLY FELT READY
TO TRY AND FORGIVE HIM.
- YOU SURE YOU CAN TRUST HIM?
HE MIGHT JUST BE
MANIPULATING YOU AGAIN.
- YOU THINK I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MY OWN FATHER IS CAPABLE OF?
- NO.
NO, I DIDN'T MEAN--
- YOU DON'T GET TO DISAPPEAR
FOR THREE YEARS
AND THEN ACT LIKE YOU KNOW
WHAT'S BEST FOR ME.
- IT'S NOT LIKE I PLANNED
TO BE GONE THAT LONG.
I WANTED TO COME BACK, BUT I
NEVER FELT READY UNTIL NOW.
- AS MUCH AS I'M ENJOYING
THIS LITTLE CATCH-UP,
MY ROYAL BLADDER
IS ABOUT TO EXPLODE.
MAKO?
COME ON,
I NEED YOU TO STAND GUARD.
- I'M NOT GONNA HOLD YOUR HAND
EVERY TIME YOU HAVE TO EMPTY
YOUR ROYAL BLADDER.
GO TO THE BATHROOM ON YOUR OWN
FOR ONCE.
- FINE.
- DO YOU ALWAYS GO
TO THE BATHROOM WITH HIM?
- I DON'T GO "WITH HIM"
WITH HIM.
I JUST STAND THERE IN THE
GENERAL VICINITY WHILE HE--
I DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT.
- GOOD AFTERNOON, SIR.
PERHAPS A SPRITZ OF COLOGNE
TO FRESHEN UP?
- MAKE IT A DOUBLE, BUDDY.
[coughing]
MAKO, HELP!
WU DOWN.
WU...
DOWN.
[groans]
- [grunting]
I WISH PABU WERE HERE.
HE COULD JUST CHEW US
OUT OF THIS.
- YOU KNOW WHO ELSE HAS INCISORS
SHARP AS A KNIFE?
ZHU LI.
[footsteps approaching]
- WELL, LOOK WHAT WE CAUGHT.
WONDER IF THEY WERE TRACKING US
AFTER WE ESCAPED.
- HELLO, FELLOW TRAVELERS!
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU COULD
HELP US OUT OF THIS NET?
- WHY WOULD WE FREE A COUPLE
OF LOWLY EARTH EMPIRE SOLDIERS?
- LOWLY?
WE WERE PART OF KUVIRA'S
INNER CIRCLE!
- WERE!
NOT ANYMORE.
WE JUMPED SHIP.
PLEASE JUST LET US OUT.
- I THINK I KNOW JUST WHAT TO DO
WITH A COUPLE OF KUVIRA'S
TOP MEN.
snap!
- AHH!
- I WONDER WHAT'S TAKING WU
SO LONG.
HE'S NOT ONE TO MISS OUT
ON LUNCH.
I'LL GO CHECK ON HIM.
WU, YOU IN HERE?
COME ON, YOUR OCTOPUS FRITTERS
ARE GETTING COLD.
[rattling]
- I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
EXCUSE ME, DID YOU HAPPEN TO SEE
IF PRINCE WU CAME OUT THIS WAY?
- SORRY, MISS.
HAVEN'T SEEN HIM.
- HMM.
I'M IN LAUNDRY.
- AH!
[grunts]
[engine turns over, car starts]
[tires squeal]
THEY'VE GOT WU!
GET THE CAR,
I'M GOING AFTER THEM.
[tires screech]
- GET IN.
[tires squeal]
- AH!
WE'RE LOSING THEM.
- HANG A RIGHT
AT THE NEXT BLOCK.
WE CAN CUT THEM OFF ON SEVENTH.
YOU MISSED THE TURN!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- I KNOW THESE STREETS
BETTER THAN YOU.
I BUILT SOME OF THEM.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
SIT DOWN.
- WHERE IS HE?
- WHOA!
[brakes squeal]
- WU'S NOT HERE.
THIS GUY WAS THE ONLY ONE
IN THE TRUCK.
- [grunts]
- WHERE'S THE PRINCE?
- HALFWAY TO KUVIRA BY NOW.
[grunts]
ALL HAIL THE GREAT UNITER.
- THEY MUST HAVE MOVED WU
TO A DIFFERENT VEHICLE
WHEN WE LOST SIGHT OF THEM.
[sirens blaring]
- [grunts]
- TAKE THIS GUY IN FOR BOOKING.
CHARGE HIM WITH KIDNAPPING.
AND TELL CHIEF BEIFONG
THAT PRINCE WU IS MISSING.
PUT OUT AN ALL POINTS BULLETIN.
WE'LL KEEP LOOKING.
- WHERE DO WE START?
THERE ARE THOUSANDS OF CARS
IN THE CITY
AND HE COULD BE IN
ANY ONE OF THEM.
- OR THEY MIGHT TRY SMUGGLING
HIM OUT ON AN AIRSHIP.
- OR MAYBE A BOAT.
- HE COULD BE ANYWHERE!
[groans]
THE ONE TIME I DON'T WATCH HIM
PEE AND THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS.
- THEY'RE TAKING WU
TO THE TRAIN STATION!
- ARE YOU SURE?
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
- I'LL EXPLAIN ON THE WAY,
JUST DRIVE!
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME!
- SO HOW DID A BUNCH
OF WATER AND FIRE BENDERS
END UP IN ONE OF KUVIRA'S
REEDUCATION CAMPS?
- CALL IT WHAT IT IS--
A PRISON.
- KUVIRA'S BEEN PURGING STATES
OF ANYONE
WHO'S NOT OF EARTH KINGDOM
ORIGIN AND LOCKING THEM UP.
- PURGING?
- WHAT ARE YOU ACTING
SO SURPRISED FOR?
YOU MUST HAVE KNOWN
WHAT SHE WAS UP TO,
BEING PART OF HER "INNER CIRCLE"
AND ALL.
- NO, I SWEAR.
AND THE INNER CIRCLE THING
LASTED, LIKE, LESS THAN A DAY.
- WILL YOU AT LEAST TELL US
WHERE YOU'RE TAKING US?
- THE BORDER CHECKPOINT.
YOU'RE GONNA HELP US
TALK OUR WAY PAST
SOME EARTH EMPIRE SOLDIERS.
- AND ONCE WE'RE THROUGH,
WE'LL SEE ABOUT LETTING YOU GO.
[grunting]
- HA HA!
LAVA TIME!
BET YOU DIDN'T EXPECT THAT!
- LOOK, I'M SORRY FOR
WHAT HAPPENED TO ALL OF YOU,
BUT AS I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO EXPLAIN,
WE DON'T WORK FOR KUVIRA
ANYMORE.
- YEAH, IF OUR HANDSOME MUGS
GET RECOGNIZED
TRYING TO GO THROUGH
THAT CHECKPOINT,
WE'RE GONERS!
- IF YOU REALLY ARE FUGITIVES,
YOU BETTER LISTEN UP.
WE'VE BEEN SCOUTING THIS REGION
FOR DAYS.
THERE'S A WALL STRETCHING ALONG
THE ENTIRE BORDER
AND PATROLS GUARDING EVERY PART
OF IT.
THAT CHECKPOINT IS OUR ONLY WAY
OUT.
- IT'S NOT WORTH THE RISK,
BARAZ.
HOW DO WE KNOW
THEY WON'T TURN US IN?
- IF HE WANTED US GONE,
WE'D BE AT THE BOTTOM OF A POOL
OF LAVA RIGHT NOW.
IF ANY OF US WANT TO GET OUT
OF THE EARTH EMPIRE ALIVE,
WE'LL HAVE TO TRUST EACH OTHER.
- ALL RIGHT,
WHERE'S THIS CHECKPOINT?
[tires squeal]
- SO HOW DO YOU KNOW WHERE WU IS
JUST BY TOUCHING
SOME SPIRIT VINES?
- I LEARNED HOW TO CONNECT TO
PEOPLE'S ENERGY THROUGH THEM.
- WHO TAUGHT YOU THAT?
- LIN'S MOM.
I FOUND HER IN THE SWAMP.
THAT PLACE IS LIKE
ONE GIANT SPIRIT WILD.
- YOU MET TOPH?
WHAT WAS SHE LIKE?
A CRANKY, MORE MISERABLE VERSION
OF LIN.
- IS THAT EVEN POSSIBLE?
- YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
- WHICH TRAIN IS WU ON?
- I DON'T KNOW!
- SPLIT UP AND START LOOKING.
- [whispers]
FOLLOW MY LEAD.
- GOOD AFTERNOON, SIR.
CAN WE HELP YOU?
- YOU SURE CAN.
WE CAPTURED THESE ESCAPED
PRISONERS.
WE NEED TO GET THEM
TO A SECURE FACILITY.
- WHERE'D THEY ESCAPE FROM?
- CAMP 14.
- THEN WHY ARE YOU BRINING
THEM THROUGH HERE?
CAMP 14'S BACK THE OTHER WAY.
- YOU THINK WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE CAMP 14 IS?
KUVIRA WANTS THEM TRANSFERRED.
- THEN I'LL NEED TO SEE
THE TRANSFER ORDER.
- LISTEN, PAL, I HAD TO FIGHT
OFF 2 BADGER-MOLES,
6 WOLF-BATS, AND 18 HOG-MONKEYS
TO GET THESE GUYS.
SO SORRY IF I DON'T HAVE
THE PAPERWORK.
I WAS TOO BUSY CRAMMING IT
IN A HOG-MONKEY'S MOUTH
WHILE IT WAS TRYING TO EAT ME.
I AM IN SORE NEED OF A SHOWER
AND I HAVE BLISTERS THAT ARE
THE SIZE OF CANTALOUPES
AND TWICE AS JUICY!
SO YOU CAN LET US THROUGH,
OR YOU CAN GIVE ME YOUR NAME
AND RANK
AND I'LL PASS IT ON TO KUVIRA.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
TO SOLDIERS
WHO QUESTION HER ORDERS,
DON'T YOU?
BAD STUFF!
- LET THEM THROUGH!
- WAIT!
STOP THEM!
THEY'RE TRAITORS TO THE EMPIRE!
- THERE'S NO WAY I'M GOING BACK
TO PRISON!
[grunts]
- AH. AH!
AH!
- [grunting]
- AH!
- [laughs]
- [grunts]
[groaning]
- BOY, I SURE HOPE THIS WORKS.
[laughs]
I STILL GOT THAT VARRICK TOUCH.
WE'RE CLEAR.
COME ON!
- AH!
- VARRICK, WAIT!
WE CAN'T LEAVE THEM.
- AH!
- RETREAT!
- THANKS.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO COME BACK.
- YEAH,
I KIND OF DID.
LET'S GO.
- [over P.A]
THE 4:15 BOUND FOR OMASHU
IS NOW LEAVING
ON TRACK NUMBER SIX.
ALL ABOARD!
- IF WE DON'T FIND WU SOON,
WE MIGHT NEVER FIND HIM.
- HE'S ON THAT TRAIN!
- HOW DO YOU KNOW FOR SURE
HE'S HERE?
- I DON'T.
BUT I HAD A FEELING, OKAY?
- AND I'M JUST SUPPOSED TO TRUST
"AVATAR FEELINGS"?
- YOU WOULDN'T HAVE TO
IF YOU HAD GUARDED THE PRINCE
LIKE YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO.
- OH, SO IT'S MY FAULT
WU DISAPPEARED.
- IT'S CERTAINLY NOT MINE!
- GUYS, SHH.
LISTEN.
[pounding]
- [shouting]
- WU!
WU, IT'S ME.
- MAKO?
WHERE AM I?
AM I DEAD?
- NO, YOU'RE ON A TRAIN.
WE'RE GONNA GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
- GAH!
- AH!
- EVERYONE OUT.
- I'M NOT GOING UP THERE.
AH!
[groans]
- [grunts]
- AH!
- JUMP!
[groaning]
- [sighs]
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YES!
THANK YOU, THANK YOU, THANK YOU,
THANK YOU, THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
YOU ARE DEFINITELY
GETTING A RAISE, BUDDY.
- YOU SHOULD BE THANKING KORRA.
WE NEVER WOULD HAVE FOUND YOU
WITHOUT HER.
- I OWE YOU MY LIFE, AVATAR.
IF ONLY THERE WAS SOME WAY
TO REPAY YOU.
OOH, I KNOW.
HOW ABOUT I TAKE YOU OUT
FOR A NIGHT ON THE TOWN?
- REALLY?
YOU'RE ASKING ME OUT RIGHT NOW?
- SO... I'LL PUT YOU DOWN
FOR A "MAYBE"?
- HOW ABOUT A NEVER?
NOT EXACTLY WHAT I IMAGINED
FOR OUR FIRST DAY BACK TOGETHER.
- BUT IT WAS KIND OF LIKE
OLD TIMES.
EXCEPT FOR THE GETTING ON EACH
OTHER'S NERVES PART.
- ACTUALLY, THAT IS LIKE
OLD TIMES FOR ME AND KORRA.
- I'M SORRY THINGS GOT SO TENSE
EARLIER.
- IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I GUESS AFTER BEING APART
FOR THREE YEARS,
THERE'S BOUND TO BE A BIT
OF AN ADJUSTMENT PERIOD.
- YEAH, BUT IT'S GREAT
TO HAVE YOU BACK.
- THERE'S NO PLACE ELSE
I'D RATHER BE.
- MM.
YOU GUYS ARE THE GREATEST
FRIENDS A GUY COULD HAVE.
- SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO
WITH HIM?
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS TO TAKE HIM
BACK TO THE HOTEL.
- WHOO.
YOU'RE TELLING ME!
I NEED A CUSHY SAFE HOUSE
SOMEWHERE.
- I THINK I KNOW JUST THE PLACE.
- NICE DIGS, MAKO.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
YOU CAME FROM MONEY.
- I DON'T.
THIS IS ASAMI'S PLACE.
SHE WAS NICE ENOUGH
TO LET MY FAMILY STAY HERE
AFTER THEY FLED BA SING SE.
- MAKO!
IT'S SO WONDERFUL TO--
[gasps]
ARE YOU...
- GRANDMA,
THIS IS PRINCE WU.
HE NEEDS TO STAY WITH YOU AND
THE FAMILY FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
- IT'S AN HONOR,
GRANDMA MAKO.
- [sighs]
- SHE LOVES ROYALTY.
- I THINK I'LL FIT RIGHT IN
HERE.
THANKS FOR LOOKING OUT FOR ME,
MAKO.
NOW WHERE'S THE NEAREST
BATHROOM?
I HAVE BEEN HOLDING IT ALL DAY!
- I KNOW IT MIGHT NOT MEAN MUCH
COMING FROM A GUY
WEARING THIS UNIFORM,
BUT I'D LIKE TO APOLOGIZE FOR
WHAT KUVIRA'S PUT YOU THROUGH.
- I APPRECIATE THAT.
- GUESS THIS IS WHERE
WE PART WAYS.
- IT'S BEEN A BLAST!
- WE'RE HEADING NORTH TOO.
WHY DON'T YOU COME WITH US?
IT'S THE LEAST WE CAN DO
AFTER YOU SAVED OUR NECKS.
- ON THAT HUNK OF JUNK?
NO THANKS.
I'M ALLERGIC TO DROWNING.
OOF!
I MEAN, UH,
WE'D LOVE A LIFT!
EW.
UH.
[groaning]
[monitor whirring]
- THIS AREA IS OVERRUN
WITH SPIRIT VINES
AND THEY APPEAR TO BE
EVEN MORE POWERFUL
THAN THE SAMPLES WE TOOK
FROM REPUBLIC CITY.
- PERFECT.
HARVEST THESE VINES
UNTIL THERE'S NOTHING LEFT.
[saws buzzing]