- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- AVATAR KORRA IS BACK
AND YOURS TRULY, SHIRO SHINOBI,
COULDN'T BE MORE THRILLED.
IT'S BEEN MY HONOR
TO BRING YOU NEWS
OF KORRA AND HER FRIENDS
OVER THE YEARS.
SO MANY HEART-POUNDING MOMENTS!
WHO CAN FORGET AMON
AND HIS EQUALIST REVOLUTION?
I STILL HAVE NIGHTMARES!
THEN THERE WAS THAT TIME
I COVERED THE NUKTUK
MOVER PREMIERE.
BOY, WAS THAT FUN.
BUT ENOUGH ABOUT ME.
SIT BACK, RELAX, AND TAKE A TRIP
DOWN MEMORY LANE.
- YOU KNOW, THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT BEING KIDNAPPED
THAT MAKES A GUY REALIZE HE
NEEDS TO GET HIS ACT TOGETHER.
- YEAH, I AGREE.
LET'S TOUGHEN YOU UP.
- AHH!
I WASN'T READY!
WU DOWN!
- [gasps]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- [moaning]
- MAKO, HOW DARE YOU INJURE
THE PRINCE?
WOULD HIS ROYAL HIGHNESS LIKE
A CHERRY-BERRY LEMONADE?
- AND MAYBE SOME OF THOSE
STICKY DUMPLINGS TOO?
- LOOK AT YOU.
YOU'RE SO WEAK, "WU DOWN"
IS YOUR CATCHPHRASE.
- I KNOW, I'M A WIMP.
BUT IT'S NOT MY FAULT.
I WAS BORN THAT WAY.
I'M NOT LIKE YOU, MAKO.
I WASN'T RAISED BY
A PACK OF COPS IN THE WOODS.
- YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT ME, DO YOU?
- YEAH, I'M DRAWING A BLANK.
WHY IS THAT?
HOW DO I NOT KNOW STUFF
ABOUT YOU?
- UH...
YOU NEVER ASKED?
- WELL, I'M ASKING NOW.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE FOOD?
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE COLOR?
IS THERE A SPECIAL LADY
IN YOUR LIFE?
- NOT SINCE KORRA AND I
BROKE UP.
- WHAT? YOU DATED THE AVATAR?
SIT.
YOU AND I NEED TO HAVE
A LITTLE GAB SESSION RIGHT NOW.
HOW'D YOU GUYS FIRST MEET?
- BOLIN AND I WERE PLAYING
FOR THE FIRE FERRETS.
- YOU WERE A PRO-BENDER?
- [sighs]
YES.
WILL YOU JUST LET ME
TELL THE STORY?
- CARRY ON.
- BOLIN AND I GREW UP DIRT POOR,
SO ONCE I BECAME A PRO-BENDER,
I WANTED IT ALL:
RICHES, FAME, ACCOLADES.
BUT ALL THAT CHANGED
WHEN I MET KORRA.
- COME HERE.
I WANT YOU MEET MY BROTHER,
MAKO.
- MAKO?
WOW, I HEARD YOU PLAY
ON THE RADIO.
- COME ON, BOLIN, WE'RE UP.
- WHOA, THAT WAS THE FIRST TIME
YOU MET?
KIND OF RUDE THERE, BUDDY.
- KNOW WHAT ELSE IS RUDE?
INTERRUPTING.
KORRA PROVED TO BE
AN AMAZING PRO-BENDER,
AND A LOYAL FRIEND.
SHE HELPED ME SAVE BOLIN WHEN
HE WAS TAKEN BY THE EQUALISTS.
AFTER GOING THROUGH
SUCH A CRAZY EXPERIENCE,
I FELT LIKE KORRA AND I
HAD A POWERFUL CONNECTION.
- SO THEN YOU SMOOCHED HER
REAL GOOD?
HUH? HUH?
- NOT EXACTLY.
AH!
[grunting]
- OH, NO.
I'M SO SORRY.
I DIDN'T SEE YOU.
- HOW COULD YOU NOT SEE ME?
I MEAN, I WAS JU--
I WAS--
I-I--WOW.
THAT WAS--
[clears throat]
- WAIT.
THAT WAS THE FIRST THING
YOU SAID TO ASAMI?
YOU REALLY GOT TO WORK ON
YOUR INTRODUCTIONS.
- HEY, WHEN YOU GOT CHARM
LIKE MINE,
YOU DON'T NEED INTRODUCTIONS.
HANGING OUT WITH ASAMI
WAS AWESOME,
BUT IT MADE THINGS WITH KORRA...
COMPLICATED.
- SO I WAS THINKING WE SHOULD
SPEND SOME TIME TOGETHER.
LOOK, I REALLY LIKE YOU
AND I THINK WE WERE MEANT
FOR EACH OTHER.
- KORRA, I'M REALLY SORRY
BUT...
I JUST DON'T FEEL THE SAME WAY
ABOUT YOU.
- THAT'S HARSH, MAKO.
- I KNOW, AND THE WORST PART
ABOUT IT IS,
IT WASN'T TOTALLY TRUE.
WE NEED TO TALK.
- SAVE YOUR BREATH.
YOU'VE ALREADY MADE IT CLEAR
HOW YOU FEEL ABOUT ME.
- NO, I HAVEN'T.
WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY IS...
AS MUCH AS YOU DRIVE ME CRAZY,
I ALSO THINK
YOU'RE PRETTY AMAZING.
- HOT DOG!
SMOOCH CITY HERE WE COME.
YOU PLAYER.
- [slurps]
WHOA.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE DATING ASAMI.
- TU, GET OUT OF HERE!
- NAUGHTY MAKO.
YOU TAKE AFTER YOUR GRANDFATHER.
- GUYS, GRANDMA,
EVERYTHING WASN'T SO CUT
AND DRY.
I WASN'T DATING ASAMI.
- DENIAL.
- OKAY, MAYBE I WAS DATING HER.
IT WAS ALL VERY CONFUSING.
BUT MY FEELINGS FOR KORRA BECAME
CLEAR WHEN TARRLOK CAPTURED HER.
IT FELT LIKE A PIECE OF ME
WAS GONE.
I WAS SO WORRIED.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- I'M FINE.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
- OOF.
I BET ASAMI WASN'T TOO HAPPY
ABOUT THAT.
- I'VE NOTICED
HOW YOU TREAT KORRA...
HOW YOU ACTED
WHEN SHE WAS MISSING.
YOU HAVE FEELINGS FOR HER,
DON'T YOU?
- THINGS ARE CRAZY RIGHT NOW.
CAN WE DEAL WITH OUR
RELATIONSHIP PROBLEMS LATER?
- WELL, THERE MIGHT NOT BE
ANY RELATIONSHIP
TO WORRY ABOUT LATER.
- ASAMI!
[sighs]
- OUCH.
- YUP.
TURNS OUT SHE WAS RIGHT.
IT WAS TIME TO MAN UP
AND CALL IT QUITS.
ASAMI,
I'M SORRY THINGS GOT
SO MESSED UP BETWEEN US.
BUT WHATEVER HAPPENS TODAY,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
HOW MUCH I CARE ABOUT YOU.
- I CARE ABOUT YOU TOO.
- WAIT, WAS THAT SUPPOSED TO BE
YOU BREAKING UP WITH HER?
- YES.
THAT WAS A BREAKUP.
- DIDN'T SOUND LIKE A BREAKUP.
- IT WAS MUTUAL.
WE HAD AN UNDERSTANDING.
WE BOTH KNEW--
CAN I JUST GET ON WITH THE REST
OF MY STORY OR WHAT?
- FINE.
BUT I HOPE YOU WEREN'T
AS AMBIGUOUS WITH KORRA
AS YOU WERE WITH ASAMI.
- TRUST ME,
I WASN'T.
KORRA AND I ENDED UP
STOPPING AMON TOGETHER
AND AFTER THAT, I WAS FINALLY
ABLE TO TELL HER HOW I FELT.
EXACTLY HOW I FELT.
I LOVE YOU, KORRA.
- I LOVE YOU TOO.
- AWW.
AND THEN YOU TWO LIVED
HAPPILY EVER AFTER?
- UM...
TENZIN'S JUST TRYING TO HELP YOU
BECOME THE BEST AVATAR
YOU CAN BE.
- OF COURSE YOU TAKE HIS SIDE.
- I'M NOT TAKING HIS SIDE.
- YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES I WONDER
WHOSE SIDE YOU'RE ON.
- THERE AREN'T ANY SIDES!
- HOW COULD YOU TAKE HIS SIDE?
- WHAT'S WITH YOU AND SIDES?
- WELL, EXCUSE ME, OFFICER!
DON'T LET ME STAND IN THE WAY
OF YOU WRITING TICKETS.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO SAVE THE WORLD!
- WELL, I GUESS THAT IF WE'RE
BOTH PUTTING OUR JOBS FIRST,
MAYBE THERE'S NO ROOM
FOR OUR RELATIONSHIP.
- SO WHAT?
ARE YOU BREAKING UP WITH ME?
- YEAH.
I GUESS I AM.
- NOW THAT'S A BREAKUP!
- AFTER THAT,
I DOVE INTO MY WORK.
SOMEONE HAD BEEN TAKING OUT
SUPPLY SHIPS
HEADING TO THE SOUTHERN WATER
TRIBE.
ASAMI'S COMPANY
WAS ONE OF THE VICTIMS,
SO SHE AND I WORKED TOGETHER TO
CATCH THE PERPS.
THE STAKEOUT WAS THE PERFECT WAY
TO GET MY MIND OFF KORRA.
IT WAS AN INTENSE NIGHT.
ASAMI AND I DISCOVERED THE
TRIADS HAD DOUBLE CROSSED US.
WE BARELY GOT AWAY,
BUT BY THEN ASAMI'S WAREHOUSE
HAD BEEN CLEARED OUT.
- MY COMPANY...
IT'S OVER.
I GIVE UP.
- WELL,
I'M NOT GIVING UP ON YOU.
I KNOW, I KNOW.
DON'T TELL ME.
I HAD NO RIGHT KISSING ASAMI.
- NO, ACTUALLY,
I'M COMPLETELY FINE WITH THAT.
YOU OFFICIALLY BROKE UP
WITH KORRA
AND THEREFORE, YOU'RE FREE TO
SMOOCH WHOEVER YOU WISH.
- IF ONLY IT HAD BEEN
THAT SIMPLE.
- [moans]
MAKO, I MISSED YOU SO MUCH!
- KORRA,
HEY, I MISSED YOU TOO.
SO YOU'RE NOT STILL MAD AT ME?
WE HAD THAT FIGHT
BEFORE YOU LEFT, REMEMBER?
- NOT REALLY.
I GOT ATTACKED BY A DARK SPIRIT
AND I LOST MY MEMORY
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
MAYBE IT HASN'T ALL
COME BACK YET.
WAS IT A BAD FIGHT?
- AHH...
HMM...
NO.
IT WASN'T THAT BAD.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
SO YOU WERE BACK WITH ASAMI,
BUT THEN KORRA CAME BACK
AND THOUGHT YOU GUYS
WERE STILL TOGETHER
AND YOU DIDN'T TELL HER
YOU WEREN'T?
- JUST LIKE YOUR GRANDFATHER.
- WELL, ME AND ASAMI WERE NEVER
OFFICIALLY BACK TOGETHER.
- REALLY?
THAT AGAIN?
YOU KNOW, IT SEEMS LIKE YOU'RE
SO AFRAID TO DISAPPOINT ANYONE
THAT YOU END UP
DISAPPOINTING EVERYONE.
- TRUER WORDS
HAVE NEVER BEEN SPOKEN.
HIGH FIVE!
- WELL, EVENTUALLY,
I DID TELL KORRA
BUT BY THEN SHE ALREADY KNEW.
- WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST TELL ME
THE TRUTH IN THE FIRST PLACE?
- I KNOW I SHOULD HAVE,
BUT...
I DIDN'T WANT TO HURT YOU
ALL OVER AGAIN.
I GUESS PART OF ME WANTED TO
FORGET ABOUT THE BREAKUP TOO.
- I THINK WE BOTH KNOW
THAT THIS...
US...
DOESN'T WORK.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
- IT'S OVER.
FOR REAL THIS TIME.
- AFTER HARMONIC CONVERGENCE,
THE WORLD CHANGED.
TEAM AVATAR TRAVELED AROUND
SEARCHING FOR NEW AIRBENDERS.
AT FIRST, IT WAS AWKWARD
BEING AROUND KORRA AND ASAMI.
AS YOU WERE.
LADIES.
BUT THEN I REALIZED
I HAD TO REALIZE WHO I WAS
WITHOUT A LADY IN MY LIFE.
- I KNOW WHAT THAT'S LIKE.
I MEAN, TO NEED DISTANCE
FROM WOMEN,
BECAUSE I HAVE SO MANY
ALL OVER ME,
ALL THE TIME.
- ANYWAY,
I EVENTUALLY HELPED KORRA
DEFEAT ZAHEER
AND SAVE THE AIRBENDERS
AND WE DID IT AS FRIENDS.
KORRA SHOWED ME THE IMPORTANCE
OF PUTTING OTHERS BEFORE MYSELF.
AND WHENEVER I THINK OF HER,
SHE CONTINUES TO INSPIRE ME.
- WOW.
THAT STORY IS AMAZING
AND I REALLY LEARNED SOMETHING.
- YOU DID?
GOOD.
- YEAH, I LEARNED THAT I REALLY
DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT YOU.
CRAZY!
ALSO, I REALIZED
THAT LADIES ARE COMPLICATED.
NO OFFENSE, GRANDMA.
- NONE TAKEN.
- I BETTER JUST FOCUS ON
BEING A BETTER KING.
OKAY, COME AT ME.
I CAN TAKE IT.
AH!
WU DOWN!
- I BROUGHT YOU SOME TEA.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT BE COLD
OUT HERE.
- YOU'RE SO SWEET.
THANKS.
- ARE YOU OKAY?
YOU SEEM OUT OF SORTS.
- SORRY.
I'VE JUST BEEN THINKING ABOUT
SOMETHING TOPH SAID.
SHE TOLD ME THAT THE WORLD
DOESN'T NEED ME
AND IT'S BASICALLY POINTLESS
TO TRY TO STOP KUVIRA.
- THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
- AT THE TIME,
I THOUGHT SO TOO.
I FIGURED SHE WAS JUST BEING
HER NORMAL, CRANKY SELF,
BUT I'M BEGINNING TO THINK
SHE HAD A POINT.
- NO, SHE DOESN'T.
THE WORLD DOES NEED YOU.
YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
- BUT NO MATTER WHAT I DO,
THE WORLD SEEMS TO ALWAYS
BE OUT OF BALANCE.
GROWING UP, I COULDN'T WAIT
TO BE THE AVATAR.
I THOUGHT I WAS REALLY
GONNA CHANGE THINGS.
I WAS SO NAIVE.
THE FIRST TIME I SAW AMON
TAKE SOMEONE'S BENDING AWAY,
I WAS TERRIFIED.
- YOUR FIREBENDING IS GONE.
FOREVER.
- THEN MY WORST NIGHTMARE
CAME TRUE.
[groans]
- KORRA!
- NO!
[gasps]
- I TOLD YOU
I WOULD DESTROY YOU.
- KORRA, YOU'RE FORGETTING ABOUT
ALL THE GOOD THAT HAPPENED
AFTER YOU EXPOSED AMON
AS THE FRAUD HE WAS.
THE EQUALIST MOVEMENT
LOST ITS LEADER AND ITS POWER.
FREE ELECTIONS WERE HELD
IN THE UNITED REPUBLIC
AND NON-BENDERS
FINALLY HAD A VOICE.
PEOPLE HAD HOPE AGAIN
AND IT WAS ALL BECAUSE OF YOU.
- AND I WAS HOPEFUL TOO.
BUT THAT FEELING
DIDN'T LAST LONG.
AS SOON AS I DEFEATED AMON,
A NEW ENEMY TOOK HIS PLACE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I TRUSTED YOU.
YOU MADE ME THINK
YOU WANTED TO RESTORE BALANCE
WITH THE SPIRITS,
BUT THIS--THIS ISN'T BALANCE.
IT'S MADNESS!
NOW LET HER GO.
- IF YOU WANT YOUR FRIEND TO
MAKE IT OUT OF THE SPIRIT WORLD,
YOU'LL OPEN THE OTHER PORTAL
NOW.
BECAUSE OF UNALAQ,
I BETRAYED TENZIN,
OPENED THE PORTALS,
AND THREW THE SPRIT
AND HUMAN WORLDS INTO CHAOS.
IT WAS MY FAULT HE FUSED WITH
VAATU AND BECAME A DARK AVATAR.
AND I WAS HELPLESS TO STOP HIM
FROM DESTROYING RAAVA
AND CUTTING OFF MY CONNECTION
TO MY PAST LIVES.
WITH RAAVA GONE,
UNALAQ AND VAATU BECAME MORE
POWERFUL THAN EVER.
- BUT YOU BECAME MORE POWERFUL
TOO.
I MEAN, YOU TURNED INTO
A GIANT SPIRIT.
- YEAH,
THAT WAS PRETTY AWESOME.
- AND OPENING THE SPIRIT PORTALS
TURNED OUT TO BE A GOOD THING.
YOU BROUGHT BACK THE AIRBENDERS
AND CAUSE A POSITIVE SHIFT
IN THE WORLD.
- YES, BUT ZAHEER GOT AIRBENDING
TOO,
AND NEARLY KILLED ME.
IF IT WEREN'T FOR ZAHEER,
THE EARTH QUEEN
WOULD STILL BE ALIVE.
THERE WOULD HAVE BEEN NO CRISIS
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM,
AND KUVIRA WOULDN'T BE IN POWER.
THINGS ARE MORE OUT OF BALANCE
THAN EVER NOW.
NOTHING'S CHANGED!
- YOU'RE RIGHT, KORRA.
- I AM?
- SHE IS?
- IT'S TRUE, THERE WILL ALWAYS
BE NEW CONFLICTS
AND ENEMIES TO FACE.
BUT THE IMPORTANT THING
IS TO LEARN FROM YOUR ENEMIES
AND BETTER YOURSELF OVER TIME,
WHICH YOU HAVE.
YOU'VE CHANGED SO MUCH
SINCE YOU FIRST ARRIVED
ON AIR TEMPLE ISLAND.
WHEN YOU FIRST CAME HERE,
YOU WERE HOTHEADED
AND A BIT SELFISH.
BUT YOU'VE MATURED INTO
A THOUGHTFUL YOUNG WOMAN
WHO PUTS THE NEEDS OF OTHERS
BEFORE HERSELF.
THE NEW AIR NATION
IS A TESTAMENT TO THAT.
YOU SACRIFICED EVERYTHING
TO SAVE THEM.
YOU'RE AN INSPIRATION
TO THE WORLD.
- THANK YOU BOTH.
I KNOW THAT THIS KUVIRA PROBLEM
IS ONLY GOING TO GET WORSE.
BUT NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
NO MATTER HOW CRAZY THINGS GET,
I'LL ALWAYS TRY
TO RESTORE BALANCE.
- AND THAT'S WHEN
I MADE A SOLEMN VOW
NEVER TO EAT BARK-ONION SOUP
AGAIN.
BEEN SIX YEARS, FOUR MONTHS,
AND 14 DAYS--
UGH.
I CAN STILL TASTE IT.
- DOES ANYONE ELSE FEEL LIKE
THROWING THEMSELVES OVERBOARD?
- NOT ME!
I'VE SPENT THE LAST FEW HOURS
TUNING OUT
ALL THESE INCREDIBLY BORING
STORIES...
- HEY!
- ALL THE WHILE
MENTALLY COMPOSING
THE MOST EXCITING TALE
EVER TOLD,
SOON BECOME THE GREATEST MOVER
EVER MADE!
I PRESENT TO YOU NOW:
BOLIN, AS NUKTUK,
HERO OF THE SOUTH--
TRADEMARK VARRIMOVERS
INTERNATIONAL--
IN THE INCREDIBLE
TRUE STORY OF BOLIN!
HERO OF THE WORLD!
- WAIT, AM I PLAYING NUKTUK,
OR IS NUKTUK PLAYING ME?
- BOTH.
IT'S YOUR TRUE STORY,
BUT WE'LL CAPITALIZE
ON THE AUDIENCE
OF THE NUKTUK FRANCHISE.
DUH.
- HOW CAN YOU CALL ME
THE HERO OF THE WORLD?
I LEFT MY FRIENDS AND FAMILY
TO JOIN UP WITH A PSYCHOTIC
DICTATOR WHO IMPRISONED ME,
AND NOW I'M RUNNING BACK HOME
WITH MY TAIL BETWEEN MY LEGS.
- NYA, BA, BA, BA, BA.
YOU'RE EMPHASIZING
THE WRONG STORY BEATS.
LET ME TELL IT.
THE STORY OF BOLIN
BEGINS IN AN EXOTIC
PORT OF CALL.
A WISE SAGE, THE RICHEST
MERCHANT IN THE WORLD,
AND A HANDSOME DEVIL
ALL SIT ON A SINGLE PILLOW
IN THE LIVING ROOM
OF A LUXURY YACHT.
HOW DO THEY ALL FIT
ON ONE PILLOW?
- OOH!
GIANT PILLOW!
- WRONG!
THEY'RE ALL THE SAME MAN!
ME!
I TRY TO TEACH A SWAMI
THE POWER OF LEVITATION,
BUT HE'S TOO STUPID
TO UNDERSTAND IT,
SO I KICK HIM OUT.
"UPON WHOM CAN I BESTOW
MY AWESOME KNOWLEDGE?"
I ASK MYSELF.
THEN IN WALKS NUKTUK
WITH A TWINKLE IN HIS EYE,
A GORGEOUS DAME ON HIS ARM,
AND A SONG ON HIS LIPS.
HE BURSTS INTO A RAPTUROUS
MELODY--
♪ WHERE CAN I FIND
MY TEACHER? ♪
- OH, COME ON!
I WASN'T SINGING,
YOU WERE NOT LEVITATING.
AND ASAMI IS JUST A FRIEND,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IF YOU WANT TO TELL
MY TRUE STORY,
YOU SHOULD START FROM
WHEN I MET KORRA.
SHE CAME TO THE BENDING ARENA
ONE FATEFUL NIGHT...
- THIS PLACE IS EVEN MORE
AMAZING THAN I IMAGINED!
- NAME'S BOLIN,
BY THE WAY.
- KORRA.
- BORING!
WHEN DOES THE SINGING START?
- THERE WASN'T ANY SINGING.
all: BOO!
- YOU'RE ONSCREEN TALENT, KID.
LEAVE THE STORYTELLING
TO THE MASTERS.
SO THE TROUBLE BEGINS
WHEN THE AVATAR
IS TRAPPED IN THE SPIRIT WORLD.
THE WORLD'S MOST EVIL VILLAINS
REALIZE
THAT WITH KORRA OUT OF THE WAY,
THE TIME IS RIGHT
TO TRY TO TAKE OUT BOLIN.
SO THE WORST OF THE WORST
TEAM UP.
THEY'RE LED BY ZAHEER--
LEADER OF RED LOTUS
AND MASTER OF THE SKIES!
A FLYING CHAOTIC CHAOS MACHINE!
HE'S JOINED BY VAATU--
THE ULTIMATE FORCE OF PURE
SPIRIT EVIL IN THE UNIVERSE!
THE BIGGEST, MEANEST, SCARIEST
KITE THAT EVER FLEW!
- WAIT, ZAHEER DIDN'T TEAM UP
WITH VAATU.
HOW WOULD THAT EVEN HAPPEN?
- HOW DO YOU THINK?
[phone ringing]
- HELLO?
- HEY, IT'S ZAHEER.
- OH, HEY, ZAHEER.
- GLAD I CAUGHT YOU AT HOME.
[laughs]
- UH-HUH.
VERY FUNNY.
LIKE I CAN LEAVE
THIS STUPID TREE.
- HOLD ON.
LET ME CONFERENCE IN--
- AMON!
THE REANIMATED ZOMBIE BODY
OF THE BLOODBENDING LEADER
OF THE EQUALISTS!
- HEY, GUYS, I'M TOTALLY IN
FOR TAKING OUT BOLIN.
HE'S WAY TOO POWERFUL
AND AWESOME.
BUT CAN WE PLEASE NOT INCLUDE--
- NOT INCLUDE WHO, AMON?
- THE EVIL UNALAQ,
THE DIABOLICAL BUT INCREDIBLY
BORING AND UNPOPULAR SORCERER
FROM THE NORTH, WHO'S LISTENING
IN ON THE OTHER LINE!
- I'VE SPENT MY LIFE
TRYING TO DEFEAT NUKTUK,
I MEAN, BOLIN,
AND I KNOW JUST WHERE
TO FIND HIM--
WITH ALL THE BEAUTIFUL LADIES.
- YES, BOLIN HAD A REPUTATION
AS THE WORLD'S GREATEST
LADIES' MAN.
- OOH, NOW THE STORY'S
GETTING INTERESTING.
- AFTER LEAVING THE BEAUTIFUL
BUT EMOTIONALLY UNSTABLE
WATER TRIBE PRINCESS
AT THE ALTAR,
HE MET A FETCHING AIRBENDER,
THE HEIR TO A VAST
EARTH KINGDOM FORTUNE.
- OPAL, SO SMART AND CARING.
SO PRETTY TO SMELL...
AND SHE'LL PROBABLY NEVER
TALK TO ME AGAIN
BECAUSE I'M SO STUPID!
STUPID!
SO, SO, SO STUPID!
- PULL IT TOGETHER,
YOU LEAKY LUG.
BUT THE DARKEST MOMENT IS ALWAYS
RIGHT BEFORE THE DAWN.
FOR AT HIS LOWEST POINT,
BOLIN SOUGHT ADVICE
FROM THE MAN WHO STARTED IT ALL,
THE WISEST OF THE WISE--
ME!
FOR SOME OF MY SIGNATURE
SAGE ADVICE!
NUKTUK, I MEAN, BOLIN,
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING
FOR YOU TO DO
IF YOU WANT TO SAVE THE AVATAR
AND DEFEAT
THE FEARSOME FOURSOME.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE
IF I LIKE "FEARSOME."
I MEAN, EVIL SQUARED
MIGHT BE BETTER.
WHATEVER.
YOU HAVE TO ASSEMBLE
THE FIGHTINGEST AIRBENDER ARMY
OF ALL TIME!
BUT IT TURNS OUT THE AIRBENDER
RECRUITS ARE A SORRY LOT,
SO BOLIN BRINGS THEM TO A SECRET
MOUNTAINTOP TRAINING FACILITY
WHERE HE TEACHES THEM THE
ANCIENT ART OF DODGING FRUIT
AND BALANCING ON STICKS!
MEANWHILE,
BACK WITH ZOMBIE AMON...
- OKAY, GUYS,
I THINK WE FINALLY DITCHED HIM.
- HA HA.
VERY FUNNY.
I'M STILL ON THE LINE.
SO ABOUT THAT EVIL PLAN
TO DESTROY NUKTUK...
HELLO?
ANYONE THERE?
GUYS!
[dial tone beeping]
- AND WITH DANGER CLOSING IN,
OPAL REALIZES
HOW MUCH SHE LOVES BOLIN
AND FORGIVES HIM
FOR WHATEVER STUFF HE WAS
TALKING ABOUT EARLIER
WHICH WILL PROBABLY NOT BE
IN THE FINAL CUT
OF THE MOVER ANYWAY.
- SHE DOES?
all: AWW.
- AND SHE KISSES BOLIN,
MAGICALLY PASSING ON
THE AIRBENDER POWER OF FLIGHT!
- OKAY, THAT PART SEEMS
A LITTLE UNBELIEVABLE.
- THIS IS NO TIME FOR THINKING,
KID.
WE'RE HEADING INTO
THE BIG FINALE!
BOLIN GATHERS HIS AIRBENDER ARMY
TO FIGHT ALONGSIDE
ROTAN AND JUJI
AGAINST THE TERROR SQUARE!
MAYBE THAT'S THE NAME
OF THE BAD GUYS--
TERROR SQUARE.
WHAT ABOUT LEGION OF DARKNESS?
WELL, WE'LL PUT A FOCUS GROUP
ON IT.
BOLIN TEACHES THE AIRBENDERS
TO CREATE A GIANT TORNADO.
THEN HE FLIES AROUND IN THE SKY,
PUSHES ZAHEER INTO IT,
TURNING HIM INTO WIND
FOREVER!
BUT BOLIN DOESN'T REALIZE THAT
THE UNIVERSAL INTERPLANETARY
COMBINATION ZERO HOUR--
TALK ABOUT A TICKING CLOCK--
IS ALMOST UPON HIM!
AND WHEN JUJI SHOOTS HIS
LASER EYES AT THE EVIL UNALAQ,
THE BEAMS ACCIDENTALLY FLY INTO
THE MAGIC SPIRIT DOORWAY!
THEY BOUNCE OFF VAATU,
SETTING HIM FREE,
AND HIT BOLIN,
TURNING HIM INTO A GIANT!
BUT WHEN VAATU IS SET FREE,
THE EVIL UNALAQ,
WHO HAS ALWAYS BEEN AN
ANNOYINGLY CLINGY PERSON,
IS SO CLOSE TO VAATU
THAT THEY COMBINE
INTO ONE HORRIFYING MONSTER!
GIANT BOLIN
AND THE EVIL UNAVAATU FIGHT
TOE-TO-TOE, ZAPPING EACH OTHER
WITH THEIR LASER BEAMS
AS THEY STOMP AROUND
REPUBLIC CITY.
IT LOOKS LIKE
THE EVIL UNAVAATU MIGHT WIN,
BUT THANKFULLY,
BOLIN'S SPIRITUAL MOJO
IS SO STRONG THAT HE ATTRACTS
THE QUEEN OF THE FAIRIES!
WITH HER HELP, BOLIN TURNS
UNAVAATU INTO MAGIC DUST
AND SPRAYS HIM INTO THE SKY.
AND THAT'S WHERE
THE STARS COME FROM.
OH, YEAH,
AND HE TURNS INTO A DRAGON,
AND HE GOES INTO THE SPIRIT
WORLD AND SAVES THE AVATAR.
THE END!
[applause]
- WAIT.
YOU LIKE THAT?
IT DIDN'T MAKE ANY SENSE!
WHAT ABOUT ZOMBIE AMON?
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM, HUH?
AND-AND-AND-AND STARS
ARE MAGIC FAIRY DUST?
ARE YOU GUYS CRAZY?
ARE YOU CRAZY?
- IT'S JUST A MOVER.
DON'T OVERTHINK IT.
IT'S LIKE A RIDE.
- NEVER LET THE TRUTH
GET IN THE WAY OF A GOOD STORY,
KID.