Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar can
master all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
Korra is safely back in Republic City,
but Bolin and Varrick are still on the lam.
Weeks ago, Korra removed
the remaining poison from her body,
but the memory of Zaheer's
attack still torments her.
And after being defeated by Kuvira,
she questions if she
will ever fully recover.
Meanwhile, Kuvira has been
secretly harvesting spirit
vines from the swamp.
But how close is she
to completing her spirit energy weapon?
Everyone, mom, can we
stay together, please?
The tour's about to begin.
That's my boy... Ryu.
He used to live in the basement,
but then he got airbending,
and he's been doing
important air nation
stuff all over the world.
His father and I are here visiting him,
and we're just having the
best time in the big city.
We're so proud, right, honey?
At least he has a job now.
Mom, dad, I'm trying to work.
Fun fact, everyone:
All these vines were created by Unavaatu
when he battled giant spirit Korra
for the fate of the world.
Excuse me.
Are we in the spirit world right now?
No.
Is the spirit world in the ground below us?
No, can I just get through my cards?
Oh, honey, don't get flustered.
I'm not!
Uh, why is that vine coming toward us?
Uh, I don't see anything
about that on the cards.
I'm gonna poke it with a stick.
No! Why would you do that?
Ohh!
Oh! Oh!
Everyone back!
This tour is exciting!
Isn't he the best airbender ever...
Ugh!
Everything okay?
No, Kuvira has my family,
and no one seems to care but me.
We all care.
Don't worry. We'll get them back safely.
Guys, there you are!
I just felt a weird
surge of spiritual energy
coming from the spirit wilds.
Something's wrong.
Are you sure you felt a disturbance?
Maybe you just had some
bad food for breakfast.
I'm telling you. I felt it.
Maybe something happened
to Ryu's tour group.
We should've run into them by now.
Yeah, but it's Ryu.
They might be at the mall for all we know.
Korra, can't you feel
how strange the energy is?
No, but...
Maybe I can get a reading.
Korra, what is it? Are you okay?
It was Kuvira.
I saw her taking vines from the swamp.
It must be affecting our spirit wilds.
I bet that's what you were sensing, Jinora.
Why is she taking vines?
Whatever the reason,
I'm sure it's not good.
We have to tell Raiko.
This might help him
convince the other leaders
to finally take her down.
I'll keep looking for Ryu and the others.
I say we deal with this
Kuvira situation immediately.
Yes! Agreed!
And I know just how to get rid of her:
We tell her she won an
all-expense-paid vacation
to a tropical island.
Then when she gets there,
we reveal it was a trap...
the island's a prison!
Boom! Got her!
Or, okay, uh, I'm just spitballing here.
We march in with an army of
highly trained badgermoles!
Do we know if Kuvira has any allergies?
Look, I think we all
know what must be done.
We take the fight to her.
I don't believe attacking
is the right move,
since she hasn't done anything aggressive
toward the united Republic.
Not yet.
But Kuvira can't be trusted.
She told us that
she was going to turn over power,
and she didn't.
I'm with Raiko.
I say we go on the offensive
and start by retaking Zaofu.
President Raiko, I'm
sorry to interrupt, but...
what's going on here?
Oh, hey, Avatar Korra.
Just kickin' it world leader style,
trying to figure out
what to do about Kuvira.
For the record, I told Raiko
he should've invited you.
You invited him but not me?
Please, Korra, it's not personal.
We just thought perhaps
we called you back into
action a little too soon.
Again... him, not me?
Korra, we're in the middle of a meeting,
and we can't have people just barge in
whenever they want!
Guys!
Oh, perfect! You're all here!
Bolin?
What are you doing here?
Guards, remove these traitors!
No!
We escaped Kuvira's army!
We're back on your side now!
We have top secret information for you!
Okay, I guess we should
have opened with that line.
Listen to me.
Kuvira is making this thing that goes...
I don't know how it
works, but it has this...
It's a super weapon!
Like a regular weapon, only super!
And let me guess.
It has something to do with spirit vines.
Yes! How did you know?
I saw a vision of her
taking spirit vines from the swamp.
If she figures out how
to harness their power,
we are all doomed.
She might use the weapon
to attack Republic City.
The only way to protect ourselves
is with a preemptive strike.
My airbenders won't be part
of an unprovoked attack.
Neither will the fire nation.
But, Fire Lord Izumi,
Kuvira is a threat to the world.
She has to be stopped!
The fire nation has spent
too much of its history
fighting nonsense wars,
and I refuse to drag my
nation into another one
unless there's no other choice.
If you attack Kuvira,
you'll do it without my army.
Fine.
I'll hold off any plans of attack.
We'll go on the defensive
and fortify security on the borders.
In that, you'll have my help.
Opal, wait! Please.
I just want to say that
I'm sorry for everything.
I'm glad you're okay,
but it's a little late for sorry.
I know. I know.
I didn't listen to you,
and I sided with Kuvira,
and I helped her take
over the earth kingdom
and topple your home
and get your mom captured
and your brothers and your dad...
Wow, that does sound really bad
when I say it out loud like that.
But I'm gonna make it up to you.
Pardon me, lovebirds,
but I need a word with Opal.
Privately.
I'm sorry, kid, but Raiko couldn't convince
the other leaders to attack Kuvira.
So our family...
Looks like we're going to
have to save them ourselves.
Don't you think some other people
would agree to go with us?
This is an unsanctioned
and dangerous mission
into enemy territory.
We can't ask other people
to risk their necks for our family.
If we want to break them out,
we'll have to do it alone.
Bolin, I'm so glad you're back.
I was worried about you.
We all were.
Thanks, guys.
Mako, I'm so sorry about
the way we left things.
I'm such an idiot.
You tried to warn me about Kuvira,
and I ran off anyway, like an idiot.
You were right, and I'm just an idiot.
I hope that I'll be able
to earn your trust again.
If anyone has lost people's trust, it's me.
Ever since Kuvira kicked my butt,
no one even wants me around.
We want you around.
And, Bolin, you're not an idiot.
You were just doing what
you thought was right.
Aw, I love you guys.
And I really want to hug again.
Agh!
Ugh!
Ah!
Korra! The vines!
They're taking me!
Help!
Get everyone out of here!
Put up a perimeter.
Cancel all tours.
Somebody get ahold of Tenzin.
We got to get in there and find Jinora.
I don't think anyone should
be going in there right now.
I know I'm not the old Avatar I used to be,
but I can do this.
Be careful.
Jinora!
Hello? Anyone?
Wait. Do you hear that?
Oh! Oh!
Come on!
Korra, look.
What are those?
It's Jinora and the rest of them.
Their spirits are trapped
in the spirit world.
Let's get them out.
Don't!
You'll provoke the vines.
Let me try.
They won't open.
Maybe if I meditate into the spirit world,
I can free them.
Wait...
This isn't the spirit world.
Zaheer!
No!
You can't fight me and the poison.
No, I got it out.
You'll never get it out!
Korra, what's wrong?
It's Zaheer.
What are you talking about?
He's been haunting me
ever since I fought him.
I can't get any peace.
It's like he's blocking me
from meditating into the spirit world.
I'm here for you.
What do you need?
I want to face Zaheer.
Korra, he's too dangerous.
Even when he's locked
up, he can't be trusted.
I need to if I want to save Jinora
and the others; There's no other way.
There is another way.
I'm calling your father.
He can lead an expedition
into the spirit world
from the Southern portal.
You've lost faith in me too, haven't you?
No one thinks I'm capable
of anything anymore.
It's not that at all.
I know I can do this.
I'm just so worried for Jinora.
I can't imagine if something
happened to you too.
Tenzin, please...
I'll be okay.
Zaheer's imprisoned deep in the mountains
outside the city.
I'll call Raiko and get the clearance.
Thank you.
Pab-pabs, where are you?
Pabu!
Oh, I missed you so much!
So I don't know if you've heard,
but Opal's kind of mad at me.
I was hoping you could
help me win her back.
Awesome! Yes, I have an idea.
Hello, Pabu.
Well, it's good to see you too.
What do you got there?
Opal, you made it.
What's this?
A picnic, just for the two of us.
Well, three of us. Sorry, pabs.
So this note Pabu brought me
saying you broke both of your legs
was just a ruse?
Maybe...
But now that you're here,
don't you want to just sit back, relax,
try some of my homemade steam buns...
Pema's recipe...
and watch Pabu do some of his
world famous backflips for entertainment?
Ha-ha!
Oh, steam buns... my favorite.
This will totally make me forget
that you worked for Kuvira,
the person who captured my family
and is probably torturing them right now.
So, yeah, let's just sit down
and have a great picnic
because we're so in love!
I'm sorry you had to see that, Pabu.
Thank you both for coming.
It's nice to be welcomed
back with open arms.
Actually, I brought you
here out of necessity.
It's no secret I never liked you,
especially after you
tried to have me kidnapped.
Allegedly.
Right.
Everything you do is "allegedly,"
like when you took over my company
and bombed the Southern
water tribe cultural center.
I own that building!
A man has the right to
blow up his own property!
Right now, I need you to
put aside your differences.
If Kuvira really is
creating a super weapon,
we're going to need the two brightest minds
in the city working together to stop it.
What do you say, Asami?
Partners again?
Fine. I'll help.
But don't even think about
double-crossing me again.
Ow... Uh-huh.
Are you sure you're ready for this?
Yes.
I think if I see Zaheer chained up,
I'll finally realize that
he's not a threat anymore.
Approach the wall.
No.
I need to do this alone.
I figured you would
show up sooner or later.
So...
You must really be in trouble
if you came all the
way down here to see me.
I came here to look you in the eye
and tell you that you
have no power over me.
I will no longer be scared of you.
I guess it didn't work.
You still seem scared.
This was a mistake.
I know why you're here.
You don't know anything about me!
You can't go into the spirit world.
I spend most of my time
in the spirit world,
and it's well-known
that the Avatar's spirit
hasn't been there for a few years.
You can meditate into the
spirit world from here?
Doesn't feel very spiritually charged.
This is your problem.
Republic City is flowing
with spiritual energy,
and you can't even tap into it.
No, my problem is you.
You poisoned me!
You ruined me!
People used to think I was unstoppable,
but now they don't think
I'm capable of anything!
Blaming me is a crutch
to make you feel better,
but it's not helping you recover.
I thought seeing
you face-to-face
would put an end to all of this,
but maybe it's time I realize
I'll never be the same.
Neither of us are the same as before.
I learned to fly, but
now I'm bound in chains.
You have all the power in the world
and the freedom to use it,
but you choose to hold yourself down.
I'm not holding myself down,
but my powers have limits.
You're wrong.
That poison should've killed you,
but you were able to fight it off.
You think your power has limits;
I say it's limitless.
Whatever.
Before, you were always
talking about chaos and freedom.
Then you took out the earth queen
and created the worst dictator
the earth kingdom has ever seen.
Thanks for that.
I've heard rumors about her,
but I didn't know she
achieved so much power.
She needs to be stopped.
Well, I can't stop her
unless I get over this block.
I think I can help.
Let me lead you into the spirit world.
No way.
I can't trust you.
Maybe not.
But if you had any other options,
you wouldn't be here now, would you?
We may have been enemies once,
but for now, our interests align.
I've come this far.
What have I got to lose?
Focus on the sound of my voice,
and clear your mind.
Let it play out.
I can't!
You can.
Accept what happened to you.
Don't fear what might have been.
I have no control!
Don't be afraid.
Hold on.
I made it...
And you led me here.
Do you know where Jinora
and the others are?
No, but you do.
Raava, I missed you.
Where have you been?
I have always been inside of you.
Can you help me find Jinora?
How do I release their spirits?
You must bend the energy within.
But I'm powerless in the spirit world.
No. You're most powerful here.
In the spirit world,
you're connected to all
the spiritual energy.
Uh...
I feel all spirity.
Dad!
I'm so glad you're safe.
What happened?
How did you get out?
Korra saved us.
So...
How are you doing?
I feel whole again.
I feel good.
Do you think you're finally able
to forget about what Zaheer did to you?
No.
But I am finally able
to accept what happened,
and I think that's gonna make me stronger.
Where are you going?
We've got some family
business to take care of.
All right, listen, before you go,
I just want to tell you that
I understand how you feel.
I know there's nothing I could do
or no big gesture that can
make up for all my mistakes,
but that doesn't mean
I'm gonna stop trying to win you back,
because...
I love you.
Thanks for saying all of that.
You know, there is one thing
you could do to win me back.
What is it? Yes, I'll do anything!
Come on a secret mission with us.
- Where to?
- Zaofu.
We're going to rescue my family.