EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
AFTER KUVIRA HARVESTED
SPIRIT VINES FROM THE SWAMP,
THE VINES IN REPUBLIC CITY
REACTED BY ABDUCTING PEOPLE.
KORRA SAVED EVERYONE,
BUT ALL IS NOT WELL.
VARRICK AND BOLIN RETURNED
TO WARN EVERYONE
ABOUT KUVIRA'S
SPIRIT VINE SUPER WEAPON.
NOW RAIKO WANTS TO MOUNT
A DEFENSE
AGAINST THE EARTH EMPIRE.
MEANWHILE, BOLIN, OPAL,
AND LIN ARE ON A MISSION
TO RESCUE SU BEIFONG
AND HER FAMILY,
WHO ARE BEING HELD CAPTIVE
BY KUVIRA.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S DO THIS.
SAVING THE BEIFONGS
AND SAVING OUR LOVE
BECAUSE I VOW TO REPAIR
THE RIFT THAT HAS GROWN BETWIXT US
AND MAKE US WHOLE AGAIN!
YOU, ZIP IT NOW.
I HAD ENOUGH OF YOUR BABBLE
ON THE RIDE IN.
YES, MA'AM.
KUVIRA TORE DOWN
ALL THE DOMES.
WHY WOULD SHE DO THAT?
SHE'S GOT A WHOLE BATTALION
OF TROOPS STATIONED THERE.
THERE'S NO WAY WE'LL BE ABLE TO SPOT
ANYTHING USEFUL FROM HERE.
WE'LL HAVE TO GO IN
FOR A CLOSER LOOK.
DON'T BOTHER.
ALL THE PRISONERS
HAVE BEEN MOVED.
UH, HEY, CHIEF.
HEY, CHIEF.
GRANDMA TOPH!
YOU WERE ONLY UP TO MY WAIST
THE LAST TIME
WE WERE TOGETHER.
OH, MAN!
OH, I CAN'T!
THIS CAN'T BE HAPPENING!
WHAT?
DO YOU HAVE TO PEE OR SOMETHING?
NO, WELL, NOW MAYBE.
YOU'RE MY HERO!
MY NAME IS BOLIN.
I'M DATING YOUR GRANDDAUGHTER,
I MEAN, KIND OF.
I MAY HAVE SCREWED THAT UP,
BUT THAT'S WHY I'M HERE,
AND YOU'RE MY HERO!
OH, I SAID THAT.
CAN I HAVE A HUG TOO?
WHAT'S UP WITH HIM?
HE'S AN ACTOR.
SO YOU ALREADY CHECKED
THE CITY FOR SU?
HOW DID YOU KNOW
SHE WAS CAPTURED?
I'VE BEEN LIVING IN THE SWAMP
AND KEEPING WATCH ON ZAOFU
THROUGH THE VINES.
SURE, OKAY, MAKES SENSE.
BY THE TIME I GOT HERE,
THEY WERE GONE.
I SNOOPED AROUND TOWN
AND HEARD THAT THEY WERE TAKEN AWAY
TO SOME NEARBY PRISON CAMP.
WHERE WOULD THAT BE?
THERE'S A FACTORY
AND REEDUCATION FACILITY
NOT TOO FAR AWAY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
BOLIN USED TO WORK FOR KUVIRA.
HOW DID YOU END UP DATING
THE KIND OF DIPSTICK
WHO WORKS FOR KUVIRA?
USED TO!
IT'S NOT HIS SILVER TONGUE,
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
PLEASE TELL ME THIS ATTITUDE
ISN'T HEREDITARY.
GRANDMA, THIS IS JUICY.
AND I THOUGHT
APPA WAS SMELLY.
WHY WOULD YOU CHOOSE
THIS LEAKY, NASTY THING?
YOU DON'T CHOOSE YOUR BISON.
HE CHOOSES YOU.
AND ONCE HE CHOOSES YOU,
YOU CAN'T CHANGE.
BELIEVE ME.
I CHECKED.
THE BORDERS ARE SECURE,
AND TROOPS ARE GUARDING
THE RAIL LINES INTO THE CITY.
SO WHAT HAVE YOU TWO GENIUSES
COME UP WITH
TO FEND OFF KUVIRA?
IT'S A FLYING MECHA-SUIT.
ASAMI GOT THE IDEA FROM
WATCHING DRAGONFLY-HUMMINGBIRDS.
YOU CAN TAKE OFF STRAIGHT UP,
FLY IN ANY DIRECTION.
WHERE DOES THE SPIRIT RAY
COME OUT?
IT DOESN'T HAVE A SPIRIT RAY.
I'M TELLING YOU
WHAT I TOLD KUVIRA:
THAT TECHNOLOGY
SHOULD NOT BE USED.
IT'S ALREADY BEING USED
BY KUVIRA!
I NEED SPIRIT VINE WEAPONS,
AND I NEED THEM NOW!
NO. IT WAS KUVIRA'S HARVESTING
OF THE VINES IN THE SWAMP
THAT CAUSED
THE REPUBLIC CITY VINES
TO GO CRAZY
AND GRAB ALL THOSE PEOPLE.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE THE
BRIDGE BETWEEN THE TWO WORLDS.
WHY CAN'T YOU HARVEST
THE VINES?
I WON'T DO THAT,
BUT MAYBE SINCE THE SPIRITS
LOVE REPUBLIC CITY SO MUCH,
I CAN CONVINCE THEM TO HELP US
DEFEND IT SOMEHOW.
HMM.
OKAY, MAYBE WHILE THE
WEAPON GENIUSES
AND THE SPIRIT BRIDGE
ARE GETTING READY FOR BATTLE,
WE SHOULD BE EVACUATING
THE ORDINARY CITIZENS
SO THAT IF KUVIRA ATTACKS,
THEY WON'T BE HURT.
THAT'S ACTUALLY A GOOD IDEA.
PRINCE WU, YOU WORK
WITH THE POLICE TO COORDINATE
GETTING PEOPLE
OUT OF THE CITY.
NOW EVERYONE GET TO IT.
I WANT DAILY UPDATES.
NICE JOB IN THERE.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
YOU'RE STARTING TO ACT LIKE
THE KIND OF KING
- I'D LIKE TO WORK FOR.
- THANKS.
AND IF KORRA BUYS
THIS "MAN OF THE PEOPLE" THING,
I STILL MIGHT GET
TO DATE HER.
YOU ALWAYS
HAVE TO RUIN IT.
WHAT? COME ON!
WHY DO YOU THINK
GUYS DO ANYTHING GREAT?
TO PICK UP GIRLS.
EVERY WORK OF ART,
EVERY SONG,
EVERY CITY EVACUATION...
ALL FOR THE LADIES.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY,
LET'S TEST THE POWER CORE.
I WANT EVERYTHING IN ORDER
FOR THE FULL DEMONSTRATION
FOR KUVIRA TOMORROW.
LOAD THE ENERGY CAPSULE.
ZHU LI, INITIALIZE PHASE ONE.
THERE'S A PROBLEM
WITH THE CONDENSER.
IT'S BACKING UP.
SHUT IT DOWN.
I CAN'T.
THE OVERRIDE ISN'T WORKING.
EVERYONE NEEDS TO EVACUATE.
THIS THING IS GOING TO BLOW!
EVERYONE GET OUT! NOW!
COME ON, BAATAR!
IT'S TOO LATE!
THIS CHANNELING RING
WAS CRACKED.
THAT'S WHAT CAUSED THE
REACTION TO OVERLOAD.
NOW WE'RE TAKING
THIS WHOLE THING APART TONIGHT
AND CHECKING EVERYTHING.
NOTHING IS TOO SMALL.
THIS HAS TO BE READY
BY TOMORROW.
SO HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN SINCE
YOU TWO HAVE SEEN EACH OTHER?
LITTLE WHILE NOW.
COUPLE OF YEARS.
TRY 20.
AH, TIME FLIES
WHEN YOU GET TO BE MY AGE.
I'M SURPRISED
YOU CAME TO SAVE SU.
I THOUGHT YOU GUYS
DIDN'T GET ALONG.
SU AND I FINALLY WORKED OUT
OUR OLD GRIEVANCES.
GOOD, GLAD WE CAN PUT ALL THAT
BEHIND US.
RIGHT. "WE."
OKAY, THERE'S THE FACTORY.
WHOA, THAT'S ONE BIG...
THING.
I THINK I KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
FEEL THAT CAVERN
A FEW STORIES DOWN?
IT SEEMS EMPTY, BUT IT'S GUARDED
BY AN AWFUL LOT OF MECH.
RIGHT.
WHY WOULD YOU NEED SOLDIERS
GUARDING AN EMPTY CAVERN?
THEY MUST HAVE THEM IN SOME
KIND OF SUSPENDED PRISON,
SO THEY CAN'T USE
THEIR EARTHBENDING.
SOMEONE'S COMING.
HIDE!
I DIDN'T EXPECT YOU
UNTIL TOMORROW.
I JUST WANTED TO CHECK IN
TO MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING WAS ON TRACK.
IT LOOKS WONDERFUL.
WE'VE HAD
A FEW MINOR MALFUNCTIONS,
BUT WE SHOULD BE READY
FOR THE TEST TOMORROW.
YOU'VE BEEN WORKING ON THIS
THE ENTIRE TIME, ZHU LI.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THE PROBLEM IS?
IT'S A VERY COMPLEX MACHINE.
THERE ARE BOUND TO BE
SOME BUGS TO WORK OUT.
BUT YOU'RE DOING EVERYTHING
YOU CAN TO FIX THOSE, CORRECT?
OF COURSE, YOUR EMINENCE.
SHE'S LYING.
TELL THE TROOPS
AND FACTORY WORKERS
TO ATTEND
TOMORROW'S DEMONSTRATION.
I WANT THEM ALL TO WITNESS
THIS INCREDIBLE NEW WEAPON IN ACTION.
WE SHOULD BE
THINKING OF A WAY
TO TAKE OUT KUVIRA
WHILE WE HAVE THE CHANCE.
OR AT LEAST DESTROY
THE CANNON.
IF SHE TAKES THAT
TO REPUBLIC CITY,
IT COULD OBLITERATE
EVERYTHING.
I DIDN'T COME TO FIGHT
WITH KUVIRA OR DESTROY A CANNON.
I'M HERE TO SAVE MY FAMILY.
IT WILL TAKE EVERYTHING
WE HAVE JUST TO GET OUT ALIVE.
HMM.
KUVIRA WANTS
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF HER PEOPLE
TO SEE THE WEAPON
TEST TOMORROW,
SO THE FACTORY WILL BE
MOSTLY EMPTY THEN.
THAT'S OUR BEST CHANCE
TO SNEAK IN
AND FREE SU
WITHOUT BEING SPOTTED.
GOOD THINKING, BOLIN.
THANKS. I KIND OF
HAVE A HEADACHE NOW.
EXCUSE ME, SPIRIT?
CAN I TALK TO...
AND YOU'RE GONE.
JUST LIKE ALL
THE OTHER SPIRITS.
THEY'RE ABANDONING THE CITY.
SO LET ME ASK YOU
ABOUT METALBENDING.
SU TRIED TO TEACH ME, BUT
I COULDN'T GET THE HANG OF IT.
I USED TO HAVE AN ACADEMY
TO TRAIN METALBENDING.
EVEN BLOCKHEADS LIKE YOU
CAN FIGURE IT OUT
WITH THE RIGHT INSTRUCTION.
YEAH, YOU'RE
A REAL SENSITIVE INSTRUCTOR.
I DID LEARN HOW TO LAVABEND.
REALLY?
IT'S A VERY RARE ABILITY.
MAYBE YOU DO HAVE SOME TALENT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU THINK I'M TALENTED.
THAT MEANS SO MUCH TO ME
COMING FROM MY HERO.
YEAH, SHE'S REAL ENCOURAGING.
HEY, I'M BLIND, NOT DEAF.
SO HERE'S SOMETHING
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN CURIOUS ABOUT.
WHO'S LIN'S DAD?
HE WAS A GUY NAMED KANTO.
NICE MAN, BUT IT DIDN'T REALLY
WORK OUT BETWEEN US.
AND...
OKAY.
LIN, I CAN FEEL YOUR ENRAGED
BREATHING FROM HERE.
JUST SAY WHAT YOU HAVE TO SAY,
AND LET'S GET IT OVER WITH.
JUST GET IT OVER WITH?
YEAH, LET'S NOT LINGER
ON THE FACT
THAT I GREW UP WITHOUT A DAD.
NO NEED TO GET
ALL TOUCHY-FEELY ABOUT IT.
JUST ONE OF
THOSE THINGS, RIGHT?
HEY, I FORGAVE YOU
FOR ALL YOUR GARBAGE
A LONG TIME AGO,
AND SU AND I WORKED THINGS OUT.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO WANTS TO HOLD ON
TO THIS FAMILY DRAMA NONSENSE
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
FORGAVE ME FOR WHAT?
AND NOT KNOWING MY DAD
IS NONSENSE TO YOU?
IT WAS PRETTY IMPORTANT TO ME.
AND UNTIL NOW,
YOU WOULD NEVER EVEN DISCUSS IT.
YOU KNOW, AFTER SU AND I
PATCHED THINGS UP,
I THOUGHT, "MAYBE I SHOULD TRY
TO REACH OUT TO MOM."
BUT NOW THAT
WE'RE TOGETHER AGAIN,
I REMEMBER
WHY WE STOPPED TALKING.
YOU MAKE ME FURIOUS,
AND YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY.
AND WHEN I TELL YOU,
YOU DON'T CARE.
ONCE WE SAVE SU,
YOU AND I ARE FINISHED.
IF THAT'S YOUR DECISION
AND IT MAKES YOU HAPPY,
THEN FINE.
THE TEST IS ABOUT TO START.
THEY'RE GOING TO BLOW UP
THAT EMPTY TOWN
WE FLEW OVER YESTERDAY.
YOU'RE CLEAR TO GO.
COPY THAT.
WE'RE GOING IN.
THE GUARDS ARE
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THAT DOOR.
WE'LL HAVE TO BE QUIET.
SHOOT ME OVER
TO THE CAGE,
AND I CAN SWING THEM BACK
ON MY CABLE.
BOLIN, YOU'LL HAVE
TO CATCH THEM
SINCE MOM WON'T BE ABLE
TO SEE THEM.
READY?
WE'LL GET YOU OUT
ONE AT A TIME.
COME ON.
I GOT YOU!
CONGRATULATIONS
ON ALL OF YOUR HARD WORK.
THIS WEAPON IS PROOF
THAT THE EARTH EMPIRE
IS THE STRONGEST NATION
IN THE WORLD.
AND BELIEVE ME,
THIS IS ONLY THE BEGINNING!
FIRE THE WEAPON.
WHAT'S WRONG?
PROBABLY SOMETHING MINOR.
I SHOULD BE ABLE
TO FIND THE PROBLEM.
THE DISTRIBUTOR PIN IS GONE.
I SWEAR I LOCKED IT IN PLACE
YESTERDAY.
THERE'S NO WAY
IT COULD HAVE JUST FALLEN OUT.
AND THIS COULD CAUSE
THE ENTIRE WEAPON TO FAIL?
IT COULD CAUSE IT TO EXPLODE.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THIS?
NOTHING.
YOU SWORE YOUR LOYALTY TO ME,
AND I GAVE YOU
A CHANCE AT GREATNESS.
THIS IS HOW YOU REPAY ME?
YOU'RE A MONSTER.
I REGRET NOTHING.
CHAIN HER UP
IN THE TARGET TOWN.
SHE CAN SEE
HOW THE WEAPON WORKS
UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL.
OH, NO.
SWEETIE, IT'LL BE FINE.
LIN WON'T DROP YOU,
AND BOLIN WILL CATCH YOU.
NO, NO.
JUST GO.
JUST LEAVE ME.
I'LL STAY HERE.
SORRY, BUT I HAVE TO DO THIS.
AAH!
HUH?
THE PRISON.
GET THERE NOW.
SHOULD WE POSTPONE THE TEST?
I DIDN'T COME ALL THIS WAY
TO STOP NOW.
FIRE WHEN READY.
I WANT TO SEE
THAT TOWN DESTROYED.
WE GOT 'EM.
WE'RE COMING OUT.
MOM!
DAD!
THANK YOU.
LET'S MOVE.
KUVIRA CAUGHT ZHU LI
AND THREW HER IN THE TOWN.
WHAT? NO,
I HAVE TO GO SAVE HER.
YOU CAN'T GO IN THERE, KID.
IT'S SUICIDE.
KUVIRA'S ONTO US.
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
TOO MUCH TOGETHER.
I CAN'T LEAVE HER.
TOPH, YOU SAID ZHU LI WAS
LYING ABOUT FIXING THE CANNON.
SHE MUST HAVE BEEN
TRYING TO STOP IT.
FOR ALL YOU KNOW,
SHE COULD JUST HAVE BEEN
COVERING HER BUTT
BECAUSE SHE MADE A MISTAKE.
NO. ZHU LI DOESN'T
MAKE MISTAKES.
YOU GUYS LEAVE.
IF WE MAKE IT OUT,
WE'LL GET TO THE CITY SOMEHOW.
BOLIN, NO!
YOU GUYS GET OUT OF HERE.
I HAVE TO GO WITH BOLIN.
COULD BE OUR BEST CHANCE
TO STOP KUVIRA.
MAYBE TAKE OUT THAT WEAPON.
WE CAN'T LET OPAL BE
THE COOLEST.
IF YOU ALL WANT TO GET
YOURSELVES CAPTURED AGAIN
OR WORSE,
THAT'S YOUR BUSINESS.
I'M THROUGH.
WATCH OUT FOR BAATAR SR.
AND HUAN.
SO HOW HAVE YOU BEEN, MOTHER?
I TOLD YOU
NEVER TO CALL ME THAT.
SPIRITS, THIS IS THE AVATAR.
PLEASE LISTEN TO ME.
SINCE I OPENED THE PORTALS,
SPIRITS AND HUMANS
HAVE LIVED HAPPILY TOGETHER
IN REPUBLIC CITY.
IT'S ALL I COULD
HAVE HOPED FOR.
I KNOW YOU FELT THE EFFECTS
OF KUVIRA CUTTING DOWN
SPIRIT VINES.
BUT NOW ISN'T THE TIME
FOR YOU TO FLEE THE CITY.
IT'S TIME FOR YOU TO HELP ME
SAVE IT FROM KUVIRA,
WHO WAS PERVERTING SPIRIT
POWER TO USE AS A WEAPON
AGAINST OTHER HUMANS.
WE DON'T GET INVOLVED
WITH HUMAN WARS.
SPIRITS WORKED WITH UNALAQ.
HE WAS MISUSING VAATU'S POWER
DURING HARMONIC CONVERGENCE
TO FORCE SPIRITS TO FIGHT YOU.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
NO,
BUT AS THE AVATAR,
I'M HOPING THAT
YOU WILL COME TO MY AID
TO SAVE THE NEW WORLD
WE ALL SHARE.
WHAT YOU WANT IS
EXACTLY WHAT KUVIRA WANTS,
TO USE SPIRITS AS A WEAPON
IN A HUMAN WAR.
THE ANSWER IS NO.
WAIT!
PLEASE, LISTEN.
IF SPIRITS AND HUMANS
ARE GONNA LIVE TOGETHER,
WE HAVE TO WORK
WITH EACH OTHER.
OPAL?
NO. WE HAVE
TO STOP THE TEST.
WHOA.
AAH!
YOU GIVE METALBENDERS
A BAD NAME!
THANKS FOR COMING TO SAVE US,
MOM.
YEAH, THANKS, CHIEF.
I'M SORRY
FOR WHAT I SAID LAST NIGHT.
I WAS JUST...
YOU KNOW.
LOOK, I KNOW
I WASN'T A GREAT MOTHER,
BUT ONE WAY OR ANOTHER,
I ENDED UP WITH TWO GREAT KIDS.
GOOD ENOUGH TO RISK
MY BONY OLD BUTT FOR, ANYWAY.
IF YOU CAN JUST FIND SOME WAY
NOT TO HATE ME,
MAYBE THAT'S ENOUGH,
AT LEAST FOR ME.
ME TOO.
YOU KNOW, I NEVER HAD
ANY FAMILY EXCEPT FOR MY BROTHER
UNTIL A FEW YEARS AGO,
AND REUNITING WITH THEM
MADE ME REALIZE HOW SPECIAL IT IS...
ARGH, ENOUGH.
ENJOY THE RIDE BACK
TO THE CITY WITH THE GUM FLAPPER HERE.
AREN'T YOU COMING BACK
TO REPUBLIC CITY WITH US, GRANDMA?
NO, MY FIGHTING DAYS
ARE OVER.
DON'T TELL KORRA,
BUT MY BACK IS KILLING ME NOW.
THIS IS WHY
YOU DIDN'T SEE KATARA
MESSING WITH
THAT CIVIL WAR NONSENSE.
AT SOME POINT,
YOU GOTTA LEAVE IT TO THE KIDS.
I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR COMING BACK TO SAVE ME.
AND DON'T BE TOO HARD ON BOLIN
FOR WORKING WITH KUVIRA.
HIS HEART WAS
IN THE RIGHT PLACE.
I THINK
BOLIN HAS WORKED HIS WAY
OUT OF THE POLAR
BEAR-DOGHOUSE.
MWAH.
YES!
HA-HA!
WE SHOULD GET GOING.
I'M AFRAID I HAVE BAD NEWS
TO DELIVER TO REPUBLIC CITY.
KUVIRA IS GOING TO ATTACK
IN TWO WEEKS.