- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- BOLIN, OPAL, AND LIN
RESCUED THE BEIFONGS
AND ZHU LI FROM KUVIRA.
NOW THEY'RE RACING
TO REPUBLIC CITY
TO ALERT EVERYONE ABOUT
THE EARTH EMPIRE'S
IMMINENT ATTACK.
MEANWHILE,
KORRA AND TEAM AVATAR HAVE
BEEN PREPARING FOR
JUST SUCH AN EVENT.
PRINCE WU IS LEADING
AN EVACUATION EFFORT
WHILE ASAMI AND VARRICK ARE
CREATING FLYING MECHA-SUITS.
BUT WITH KUVIRA PLANNING TO
STRIKE IN ONLY TWO WEEKS,
WILL THEY BE READY IN TIME?
- TODAY WE STAND ON
THE PRECIPICE OF HISTORY.
FOR THE PAST THREE YEARS,
WE'VE FOUGHT SIDE BY SIDE
TO UNITE THE EARTH EMPIRE
AND WE'VE PROVEN THAT NO ONE CAN
STAND IN OUR WAY.
NOT EVEN THE AVATAR.
BUT OUR MISSION
IS NOT YET COMPLETE.
THERE IS A GRAVE INJUSTICE THAT
MUST BE CORRECTED.
AS YOU ALL KNOW,
AFTER THE HUNDRED YEAR WAR,
AVATAR AANG, ALONG WITH
FIRE LORD ZUKO
STOLE EARTH EMPIRE LAND AND
FORMED THE UNITED REPUBLIC.
THIS LAND BELONGS TO THE PEOPLE
OF THE EARTH EMPIRE
AND IT'S TIME TO TAKE IT BACK.
REPUBLIC CITY WILL BE OURS!
all: ALL HAIL THE GREAT UNITER!
- ARE YOU READY TO SHOW
THE WORLD
WHAT A TRUE SUPER POWER
LOOKS LIKE?
- YES. I'M HONORED TO MARCH INTO
THE CITY BY YOUR SIDE.
I LOVE YOU, KUVIRA.
- I NEVER COULD'VE DONE THIS
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
AFTER WE CLAIM VICTORY,
WE CAN FINALLY GET MARRIED
AND RULE OUR EMPIRE TOGETHER.
- HOW'S THE EVACUATION COMING?
- COULD BE BETTER.
AT THIS POINT WE'VE EVACUATED
ALMOST...18 FAMILIES.
- ONLY 18? THERE ARE MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE IN THIS CITY!
- I SAID IT COULD BE BETTER.
- THE PROBLEM IS IT'S
A VOLUNTARY EVACUATION
AND THERE AREN'T MANY
VOLUNTEERS.
THEY JUST DON'T FEEL LIKE
THEY'RE IN ANY
IMMEDIATE DANGER.
[door opens]
- GUYS! GOOD! YOU'RE ALL HERE.
- WHAT'S WITH YOU INTERRUPTING
MY IMPORTANT MEETINGS
ALL THE TIME?
- SU!
WHAT ARE YOU--YOU'RE OKAY!
I'M SO SORRY ABOUT ZAOFU.
HOW DID YOU ESCAPE?
- OPAL, BEIFONG, AND I
RESCUED EVERYONE
BUT WE HAD A RUN IN
WITH KUVIRA.
WE SAW HER SUPER SPIRIT WEAPON
UP CLOSE.
LIKE, REALLY CLOSE.
WAY TOO CLOSE.
- IS SHE GOING TO USE IT AGAINST
REPUBLIC CITY?
- YES. I FOUND OUT SHE'S GOING
TO ATTACK IN TWO WEEKS.
- OH! AND ZHU LI IS ON
OUR SIDE NOW.
ACTUALLY, SHE NEVER REALLY
SWITCHED SIDES.
AND I'M JUST GONNA LET HER
EXPLAIN THE WHOLE THING,
ZHU LI?
- I PRETENDED TO BE LOYAL TO
KUVIRA SO I COULD
SABOTAGE HER WEAPON.
IT DIDN'T WORK,
BUT I DID OVERHEAR
HER PLANS TO ATTACK.
- I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T STOP
AT ZAOFU.
- MY GUESS IS, SHE'S COMING
BY RAIL.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY SHE CAN
TRANSPORT THAT WEAPON.
- THEN WE'LL CUT THE RAIL LINES.
- I AGREE. BUT LET'S GET
AS MANY CITIZENS
EVACUATED BEFORE WE DO.
PUT OUT THE ANNOUNCEMENT.
THE EVACUATION IS NOW MANDATORY.
- WE'RE ON IT.
- DON'T WORRY, MR. PRESIDENT.
I WON'T LET KUVIRA TAKE
OUR CITY.
- WELD HOTTER! TIGHTEN TIGHTER!
THE PRESIDENT SAID WE ONLY HAVE
TWO WEEKS
TO GET THESE HUMMINGBIRDS
HUMMING!
[humming]
- VARRICK, GOOD, YOU'RE HERE.
CAN I TALK TO YOU FOR A MINUTE?
- WHAT IS IT? I'M BUSY
INSPIRING MY WORKERS.
- WELL, I WENT TO ZAOFU
AND SAVED SU AND HER FAMILY...
AND GUESS WHO ELSE WE FOUND...
HA!
- ZHU LI.
- NOW, ISN'T THERE SOMETHING
YOU WANTED TO SAY TO HER?
HMM?
- PLEASE, LET ME GO FIRST.
I KNOW I SAID A LOT OF TERRIBLE
THINGS ABOUT YOU
IN FRONT OF KUVIRA,
BUT I NEED YOU TO KNOW,
I DIDN'T MEAN ONE WORD.
WHEN YOU WERE BEING TAKEN AWAY,
I THOUGHT MY ONLY CHANCE
TO SAVE YOU WAS TO JOIN HER.
BUT EVERYDAY I HOPED FOR THE
CHANCE TO SEE YOU AGAIN
AND TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
VARRICK, YOU MEAN THE WORLD
TO ME,
AND I'M SORRY IF I HURT YOU
IN ANY WAY.
- DON'T BE SO HARD ON YOURSELF.
APOLOGY ACCEPTED!
NOW BE A GOOD ASSISTANT AND
MAN THE ASSEMBLY LINE!
- NO! I AM NOT YOUR ASSISTANT
ANYMORE!
IF YOU WANT ME AROUND,
YOU NEED TO START TREATING ME
LIKE AN EQUAL.
- [sound of indifference]
- [frustrated smack to head]
- WE'RE PATCHED IN ON
THE EMERGENCY BROADCAST LINE.
YOU'RE GOING OUT TO EVERY RADIO
IN THE CITY.
- ATTENTION CITIZENS
OF REPUBLIC CITY,
THIS IS NOT A TEST.
AN ATTACK ON OUR CITY IS
IMMINENT.
PRESIDENT RAIKO HAS ORDERED
A MANDATORY EVACUATION
FOR ALL CITIZENS.
PLEASE FIND
YOUR EVACUATION HANDBOOKS
AND TURN TO SUB-SECTION
ONE DASH TWO SIX.
THERE YOU WILL FIND INITIAL
INSTRUCTIONS FOR YOUR AREA.
FOR EXAMPLE, IF YOU LIVE IN
NORTHWEST-VECTOR-ONE
REPORT TO YOUR PRIMARY MEETING
LOCATION
WHICH WOULD BE AT
THE EASTERN ENTRANCE
OF THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE
LIBRARY.
THERE, YOU WILL CHOOSE A LEADER
AS SPECIFIED IN
SECTION ONE DASH TWO EIGHT.
[phones ringing like crazy]
- UH, CHIEF, WE'RE GETTING
CONFUSED CALLS
FROM ALL OVER THE CITY. I THINK
MAKO'S STARTING A PANIC.
- WHAT'S CONFUSING? I'M GIVING
VERY SPECIFIC INSTRUCTIONS.
- GREAT, THIS IS JUST WHAT
WE NEED.
- I GOT THIS.
HELLO, EVERYONE.
THIS IS PRINCE WU.
NOW I KNOW YOU'RE ALL
A LITTLE SCARED.
BELIEVE ME, I KNOW WHAT IT'S
LIKE TO BE AFRAID.
I USED TO NOT BE ABLE TO GO TO
THE BATHROOM BY MYSELF.
BUT IF WE LET THAT FEAR
CONTROL US,
NONE OF US WILL EVER BE ABLE TO
GO TO THE BATHROOM,
AND THEN WE ALL LOSE.
BUT THE PEOPLE OF REPUBLIC CITY
AREN'T LOSERS, WE'RE WINNERS!
WINNERS THAT ARE GOING TO GET
OUT OF THIS CITY
IN A CALM AND ORDERLY FASHION.
SO I WANT YOU TO GRAB
YOUR FAMILY,
GRAB YOUR NEIGHBOR,
GRAB THAT GUY DOWN THE STREET
YOU DON'T KNOW VERY WELL
AND HEAD TO THE NEAREST
BUS, TRAIN,
OR FERRY STATION.
WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU
OUT OF HERE,
SAFE AND SOUND.
- GOOD JOB, KID.
YOU MIGHT NOT MAKE SUCH A BAD
KING AFTER ALL.
- ROHAN'S WITH THE ACOLYTES.
THEY HAVE THE BOAT
READY TO LEAVE.
WHY AREN'T YOU ALL PACKED YET?
- THE KIDS AND I HAVE
BEEN TALKING
AND WE DECIDED WE WANNA STAY.
THIS IS OUR CITY,
AND IT'S GOING TO NEED
ALL THE HELP IT CAN GET.
- YEAH! ONLY A COWARD
FLEES HIS FATE.
- THANK YOU.
I'M SURE PRINCE WU COULD USE
YOUR HELP WITH THE EVACUATION.
AND YOU THREE CAN HELP
THE OTHER AIRBENDERS
KEEP AN EYE ON THE EARTH EMPIRE
TROOPS FROM ABOVE.
- KUVIRA WILL RUE THE DAY SHE
MESSED WITH MEELO!
- I STILL DON'T LIKE HAVING TO
ABANDON MY OFFICE AND THE CITY.
- AIR TEMPLE ISLAND IS
THE IDEAL LOCATION
FOR YOUR BASE OF OPERATIONS.
AND YOU'LL BE SAFE HERE.
- THERE'S SOMETHING WE NEED TO
DISCUSS WITH YOU.
- WHAT IS IT?
- THE FOUR OF US
HAVE BEEN TALKING AND...
WE WANT TO TAKE OUT
KUVIRA'S SPIRIT WEAPON
BEFORE IT GETS TOO CLOSE TO
THE CITY.
- THAT SOUNDS LIKE A RISK WE
DON'T NEED TO TAKE.
THE EVACUATION IS ON SCHEDULE
AND GENERAL IROH IS GETTING
HIS ARMY IN PLACE.
- I KNOW IROH CAN GO TOE TO TOE
WITH KUVIRA'S ARMY,
BUT THAT WEAPON--
- IT'S TOO POWERFUL!
IT CAN DESTROY THE CITY!
- WE CAN'T LET IT GET TO
OUR DOORSTEP.
- WE'LL SNEAK BEHIND ENEMY LINES
AND DISABLE THE WEAPON.
- IF IT WORKS, IT'LL EVEN
THE PLAYING FIELD.
- BUT IF YOU GET CAUGHT...
- IT'S WORTH THE RISK.
- I AGREE, AND IT MIGHT BE
OUR ONLY SHOT
AT PREVENTING AN ALL OUT WAR.
GOOD LUCK.
- WE'LL HEAD OUT TONIGHT.
- THERE'S SOMETHING OUT THERE.
IT'S KUVIRA'S ARMY!
THEY'RE A WEEK EARLY!
GET THE COMMANDER IMMEDIATELY,
AND RADIO REPUBLIC CITY!
[thunderous thud]
- [gasp]
[thud]
[mechanized whirring]
[bass tone]
- [gasps] GUYS, I SEE SOMETHING.
DOWN THERE!
- IS THAT?
- KUVIRA.
SHE'S ALREADY CROSSED INTO
UNITED REPUBLIC TERRITORY.
SHE'S A WEEK EARLY.
- THIS DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
THERE AREN'T ANY TRAIN TRACKS
THIS WAY.
HOW ARE THEY TRANSPORTING THAT
SUPER WEAPON OF THEIRS?
- APPARENTLY ON A GIANT
MECHA-SUIT.
- DID YOU KNOW KUVIRA WAS
BUILDING THAT THING?
- OH, DID I FORGET
TO MENTION IT?
NO! OF COURSE I DIDN'T KNOW!
- THERE'S A FLYING BISON
UP AHEAD.
- THE AVATAR...
- I KNOW WHAT HAPPENS NEXT!
WE GOTTA GET OUTTA HERE NOW!
NOW!
[all screaming]
- SHOULD WE GO AFTER THEM?
THEY'RE GOING TO WARN
REPUBLIC CITY.
- LET THEM.
NO ONE CAN STOP US.
- KORRA, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHY ARE YOU BACK SO SOON?
- IT'S KUVIRA.
OUR INTEL WAS WRONG.
SHE MUST'VE KNOW ZHU LI HAD
THE INFORMATION.
- WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY?
- KUVIRA'S ARMY IS ONLY
A FEW HOURS AWAY.
- NO, THEY CAN'T BE...
WE'RE NOT READY.
- AND THAT SPIRIT WEAPON OF HERS
IS ATTACHED TO A GIANT
MECHA-SUIT.
IT'S OVER 25 STORIES TALL.
- GET GENERAL IROH ON THE LINE
AND TELL HIM
THE ATTACK IS HAPPENING TODAY.
WE NEED TO LOCK DOWN THIS CITY.
- PEMA, FIND WU AND GET
THE REMAINING CITIZENS
TO SAFETY IMMEDIATELY.
WE CAN'T HAVE INNOCENT LIVES
IN JEOPARDY.
- WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
- LET'S GO TO MY FACTORY.
MAYBE WE CAN GET A FEW OF THOSE
HUMMINGBIRD SUITS
UP AND RUNNING.
- WE'RE COMING WITH YOU.
- I'LL HEAD TO THE FRONT LINES
AND HELP GENERAL IROH.
- KUVIRA THIS IS
PRESIDENT RAIKO.
I ORDER YOU TO STAND DOWN.
TURN YOU ARMY AROUND AND LEAVE.
- YOU'RE IN NO POSITION
TO GIVE ORDERS.
- STAND DOWN OR WE WILL ATTACK.
- I DON'T THINK YOU UNDERSTAND
THE POWER I POSSESS.
LET ME MAKE IT CLEAR.
- THIS IS EXACTLY WHY I DIDN'T
WANT TO BUILD THAT WEAPON!
- MR. PRESIDENT, DO I HAVE
YOUR ORDER TO ENGAGE?
- YOU HAVE THREE SECONDS OR I
WIPE OUT YOUR ARMY.
- I HAVE NO CHOICE.
- TIME'S UP.
- STOP. WE SURRENDER.
REPUBLIC CITY IS YOURS.
- GOOD. TURN YOUR ARMY AND
THE AVATAR
OVER TO ME AND GIVE BAATAR
YOUR LOCATION.
HE'LL PRESENT YOU WITH
OUR TERMS.
- I'M NOT SURRENDERING!
- GET BACK TO THE CITY BEFORE
SHE SEES YOU.
AND KORRA, FIND A WAY TO BEAT
THAT THING.
- I WILL.
- WE'VE DONE IT KUVIRA.
AND I JUST GOT WORD THAT
PRESIDENT RAIKO
IS ON AIR TEMPLE ISLAND.
I'M HEADING THERE NOW.
- RAIKO SURRENDERED.
IT'S DOWN TO US NOW.
- HOW ARE WE SUPPOSED TO FIGHT
AN ENTIRE ARMY,
A MECHA-GIANT,
AND THAT CRAZY WEAPON?
- WE CAN'T FIGHT IT,
BUT MAYBE WE CAN CRIPPLE IT.
ZHU LI,
WHEN YOU WERE SPYING ON KUVIRA,
DID YOU LEARN ANYTHING ABOUT
THAT METAL MONSTER.
- I HAD NO IDEA THEY WERE EVEN
BUILDING IT.
- GUESS BAATAR JR. IS A BETTER
INVENTOR THAN I THOUGHT.
DON'T TELL HIM I SAID THAT.
- [gasp] THAT'S IT!
BAATAR JR. BUILT IT--
HE'LL KNOW HOW TO TAKE IT DOWN.
I SAY WE CAPTURE HIM AND
GET HIM TO TALK.
- HMM...
- I KNOW IT'S A LONG SHOT, BUT
IT'S THE ONLY CHANCE WE HAVE
AND IF WE DON'T--
- KORRA. I'M IN.
- WE'LL NEED A STEALTH TEAM OF
AIRBENDERS TO GET IN AND OUT
OF BAATAR'S AIRSHIP UNNOTICED.
TENZIN, BUMI, JINORA, KAI--
LET'S GET MOVING.
- WHAT ABOUT ME?
- SORRY BUDDY,
BUT THIS MISSION COUNTS ON
EVERYONE BEING AS SILENT
AS POSSIBLE.
AND YOUR FARTS ARE JUST
TOO MUCH OF A WILD CARD.
- I CAN BE QUIET!
[farts]
OKAY. POINT TAKEN.
- IS EVERYONE READY?
[muffled struggling sounds]
- YOU'VE MADE
A TERRIBLE MISTAKE.
ONCE KUVIRA FINDS OUT I'M
MISSING, YOU'RE ALL DONE FOR.
- THAT'S WHY BEFORE
SHE FINDS OUT,
YOU'RE GOING TO TELL US HOW TO
STOP THAT MECHA-GIANT,
OR ELSE...
- OR ELSE WHAT?
YOU WON'T HURT ME.
I KNOW AN EMPTY THREAT WHEN
I SEE ONE.
- [frustrated groan]
- WAS THIS YOU BEST IDEA?
YOU'VE LOST, ONLY YOU HAVEN'T
ACCEPTED IT YET.
- LET ME TALK TO HIM.
- ARE YOU SURE?
- CHECK THE ENGINE ROOM.
- WHAT'S GOING ON?
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
- JUST A MINUTE, SIR.
I'M TELLING YOU, I LOOKED
EVERYWHERE.
- ALL RIGHT, ENOUGH WHISPERING.
- I'M READY TO DISCUSS THE TERMS
OF THE SURRENDER
WITH BAATAR JR.
WHERE IS HE?
- UH...
I'M NOT REALLY SURE.
- BAATAR...
- IF YOU THINK I'M GOING
TO SPILL ALL MY SECRETS TO YOU,
MOTHER,
YOU'RE SADLY MISTAKEN.
- WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
I KNOW YOU SET OUT TO HELP
BETTER THE WORLD
BUT THIS IS MADNESS!
- IT'S MADNESS TO LET OTHERS
TAKE WHAT'S YOURS
AND ACCEPT IT BLINDLY.
THE UNITED REPUBLIC
BELONGS TO US.
AND WE'RE TAKING IT BACK.
- BUT AT WHAT COST?
HOW MANY PEOPLE HAVE TO LOSE
THEIR LIVES
BEFORE KUVIRA IS SATISFIED?
- IT DOESN'T HAVE TO COST
ANY LIVES
IF YOU WOULD ALL JUST SURRENDER.
ALL THAT KUVIRA AND I WANT IS
A UNITED EARTH EMPIRE.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT I DID
TO HURT YOU,
BUT WHATEVER IT WAS,
I'M SORRY.
WHEN YOU LEFT ZAOFU,
IT BROKE MY HEART.
AND OUR FAMILY HAS NEVER BEEN
THE SAME SINCE.
PLEASE, BAATAR.
STOP ALL OF THIS AND COME HOME.
WE WANT YOU BACK WITH US.
- KUVIRA IS MY FAMILY NOW.
- WE'RE GOING ABOUT THIS
ALL WRONG.
YOU'RE RIGHT, I'M NOT GOING TO
PHYSICALLY HURT YOU
IF YOU DON'T TALK. BUT THERE IS
SOMETHING I CAN DO
THAT WILL BE EVEN MORE PAINFUL.
I WILL TAKE AWAY THE ONE THING
YOU CARE FOR THE MOST--
KUVIRA.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- KUVIRA MIGHT WIN.
SHE MIGHT CHASE US
OUT OF THE CITY.
BUT YOU WON'T BE AROUND TO
ENJOY THE VICTORY.
BECAUSE WHEREVER I RUN,
I'LL TAKE YOU.
I'M GOING TO MAKE IT MY LIFE'S
MISSION TO NEVER LET YOU
SEE THE ONE YOU LOVE AGAIN.
IS TAKING THE CITY WORTH
LOSING KUVIRA FOREVER?
- YOU CAN'T.
- I WILL.
UNLESS YOU CONVINCE KUVIRA TO
BACK OFF.
YOU TWO WILL STILL HAVE
THE EARTH EMPIRE,
JUST LEAVE
THE UNITED REPUBLIC ALONE.
- IT'S KUVIRA. SHE WANTS
TO TALK TO BAATAR.
WHAT SHOULD I TELL HER?
- FOR GOODNESS SAKE,
GIVE ME THAT RADIO.
LET ME TALK TO HER.
KUVIRA, THIS IS RAIKO.
WHAT KIND OF GAME
ARE YOU PLAYING?
YOU TOLD ME YOU WOULD SEND
BAATAR OVER WITH YOUR TERMS,
AND THEN HE DOESN'T SHOW.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN
HE DIDN'T SHOW?
- ACCORDING TO YOUR PEOPLE,
HE'S NOT ON THE AIRSHIP.
- IF HE'S NOT ON THE AIRSHIP
THEN WHERE IS HE?
- [radio transmission]
KUVIRA, IT'S BAATAR.
I'VE BEEN CAPTURED.
MY AIRSHIP WAS AMBUSHED AND
I WAS TAKEN BY FORCE.
KORRA REFUSES TO RELEASE ME
UNLESS WE BACK DOWN
AND LEAVE THE CITY.
- ARE YOU INJURED?
- I'M FINE.
- IS THE AVATAR THERE
WITH YOU NOW?
- YES. EVERYONE IS HERE.
- FIND OUT WHERE
THAT RADIO SIGNAL'S COMING FROM.
- LISTEN TO ME.
IF YOU TRY TO TAKE
REPUBLIC CITY,
THE AVATAR WILL NEVER LET ME
SEE YOU AGAIN
AND I REFUSE TO LIVE THAT WAY.
FORGET THE UNITED REPUBLIC.
WE HAVE OUR EMPIRE.
WE HAVE EACH OTHER.
LET'S GO BACK HOME AND
GET MARRIED.
THE ONLY THING THAT MATTERS IS
THAT WE'RE TOGETHER
FOR THE REST OF OUR LIVES.
- WE'VE IDENTIFIED
THEIR POSITION.
- YOU'RE RIGHT, THIS CITY
ISN'T WORTH SACRIFICING
OUR LIFE TOGETHER.
I LOVE YOU, BAATAR.
- AS SOON AS WE WORK OUT TERMS
WITH KUVIRA,
WE'LL LET YOU OUT OF HERE.
- GUYS!
SHE MUST HAVE OUR LOCATION!
SHE'S POINT THAT WEAPON
RIGHT AT US.
- NO, SHE WOULDN'T--
- EVERYONE OUT!
NOW!
- NO.
- KEEP THE PRESIDENT SAFE.
I'M GOING TO CHECK
FOR SURVIVORS.