- EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
WATER.
ONLY THE AVATAR CAN MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND BRING BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
- THE EARTH EMPIRE HAS INVADED
THE UNITED REPUBLIC!
AFTER KUVIRA
DEMONSTRATED THE POWER
OF HER SPIRIT ENERGY WEAPON,
PRESIDENT RAIKO
SURRENDERED THE CITY,
BUT THE AVATAR REFUSED
TO GIVE UP
WITHOUT A FIGHT.
KORRA HELD BAATAR JR. HOSTAGE,
HOPING TO FORCE KUVIRA
TO BACK DOWN,
BUT THE PLAN FAILED,
AND SHE FIRED
ON TEAM AVATAR'S HIDEOUT.
CAN ANYTHING OR ANYONE
STOP KUVIRA AND HER MECHA-GIANT?
- [grunting]
GO AHEAD. TAKE YOUR TIME.
JUST BENDING A GIANT WALL.
MAN, WE GOT A LOT
OF PEOPLE HERE.
IS THAT EVERYBODY?
[grunts]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[electronic grinding]
- [gasps]
KUVIRA'S HEADING OUR WAY
WITH A PLATOON OF MECHA-SUITS.
- WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
THIS IS MY HOMETOWN,
AND I HATE TO SAY IT,
BUT THERE'S NO USE RISKING
ALL OUR LIVES
TO FIGHT THAT GIANT THING.
LET HER TAKE THE CITY
FOR NOW.
WE'LL THINK OF SOME WAY
TO COME BACK AND BEAT HER.
- WHAT ABOUT ALL THE PEOPLE
WHO HAVEN'T BEEN EVACUATED YET?
IF KUVIRA FINDS OUT
WU IS WITH THEM,
SHE MIGHT FIRE
THAT SPIRIT CANNON AT HIM
AND TAKE THEM ALL OUT.
- I COULDN'T STOP KUVIRA
FROM TAKING ZAOFU.
I'M NOT LETTING HER CONQUER
REPUBLIC CITY.
THE WORLD ISN'T SAFE AS LONG
AS SHE HAS THAT WEAPON.
- I AGREE.
WE TAKE DOWN THAT GIANT TODAY.
- LIN!
- GLAD TO SEE
YOU ALL MADE IT OUT.
YOU HAD ME WORRIED.
- WELL, YOU BENDERS ARE GONNA
HAVE TO FIGHT HER ALONE.
SHE JUST BLEW UP OUR FACTORY
WITH ALL OUR HUMMINGBIRD SUITS.
- NOT ALL OF THEM.
THERE ARE THE PROTOTYPES
BACK AT MY OFFICE.
IF WE CAN GET THOSE
READY TO FLY,
WE'LL AT LEAST BE ABLE
TO OFFER A LITTLE AIR SUPPORT.
- SU, YOU TAKE BAATAR JR.
AND THE REST OF THE WOUNDED
BACK TO ASAMI'S OFFICE.
GET THOSE SUITS WORKING
AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
THE REST OF US WILL JUST
HAVE TO FACE KUVIRA ON OUR OWN.
[crowd chattering]
- EVERYONE, PLEASE SETTLE DOWN.
THE TRAINS SHOULD BE RETURNING
TO PICK US UP SOON.
- TELL THAT MECHA-JERK
TO SETTLE DOWN.
SHE'S THE ONE BLOWING UP
THE WHOLE CITY!
- I HATE TO BE THE BEARER
OF MORE BAD NEWS,
BUT I JUST HEARD ON THE RADIO
THAT KUVIRA'S ARMY
HAS DESTROYED THE TRAIN TRACKS.
WE'RE NOT GETTING OUT
OF THE CITY BY RAIL.
- EVERYONE, I WAS JUST
UP ON THE OBSERVATION DECK
AND SAW A BUNCH OF MECHA-SUIT
SOLDIERS HEADING THIS WAY!
- OH, GREAT!
THE GIANT ONE WASN'T ENOUGH?
IT'S OVER!
WE'RE ALL
GONNA GET BLOWN TO BITS!
- LISTEN, EVERYONE.
I CAN GET US OUT OF HERE
IF YOU JUST SIT TIGHT.
CAN YOU STEP OFF
THE BENCH, PLEASE?
IT'S A LITTLE CROWDED UP HERE.
- SURE.
I'M ONLY THE CONDUCTOR.
NO ONE NEEDS ME ON THE BENCH.
- JUST STAY CALM.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK. COME ON!
- WHOA! WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- I'M GOING TO GET SOME HELP.
YOU THINK YOU CAN HANDLE
THIS UNRULY MOB
FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
- I RAISED MEELO.
I CAN HANDLE ANYTHING.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- A PAINT STORE?
THAT'S IT!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING, MEELO?
- I JUST GOT AN IDEA
HOW TO BEAT THE GIANT!
NOW EVERYONE, GRAB SOME PAINT
AND FIND ME SOME BALLOONS!
[mechanical grinding]
- AIRBENDERS APPROACHING.
- I SEE THEM.
[mechanical grinding]
[electrical booming]
[all cry out]
[explosion]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- BOMBS AWAY!
- CLEAR THE GLASS.
- NOW!
- THE JOINTS ARE PLATINUM, TOO!
WE CAN'T METALBEND ANY OF IT!
- YOU'RE ABOUT TO GET
THE WORLD'S LARGEST HOT-FOOT,
METAL LADY!
- [grunts]
- HIT IT NOW!
[mysterious music]
♪ ♪
[explosion]
[wood cracking]
- [grunts]
[rocks clattering]
[electrical booming]
[cries and shouts]
- AH! AH!
[explosions and rubble falling]
[glass shattering]
AH! UH! UH!
[breathing heavily]
- OPAL!
[booming]
[metal creaking]
- EVERYONE, RETREAT.
TAKE THE WOUNDED BACK
TO ASAMI'S OFFICE.
- I'LL MEET YOU THERE.
I'M GOING TO SEE
IF I CAN FIND HELP.
[explosion]
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- ALL RIGHT.
LET'S FIRE IT UP AGAIN.
[mechanical humming]
[engine rumbling]
[wings fluttering]
- I CAN'T STABILIZE IT!
I THOUGHT YOU FIXED
THE HYDRAULICS.
- I DID!
TWIST HARDER!
[mechanical grinding]
- AH-AH-OH!
- I HOPE YOU HAVE SOMETHING
IN HERE
THAT CAN TAKE OUT A PLATOON
OF MECHA-SUITS.
KUVIRA'S TROOPS
ARE HEADED THIS WAY!
- I KNOW HOW TO TAKE DOWN
SOME MECHA-SUITS,
AND IT JUST MIGHT TAKE DOWN
THAT GIANT, TOO!
ASAMI, DISCONNECT ANYTHING
ELECTRICAL IN HERE
UNTIL WE GET BACK.
ZHU LI, LET'S GO.
- WHERE AM I?
MOM?
- JUST REST, SON.
I'M HERE.
- MOM, I'M SO SORRY.
I BETRAYED YOU--
THE WHOLE FAMILY.
I GAVE MY LIFE TO KUVIRA,
AND SHE JUST FIRED
THAT WEAPON AT ME.
HOW COULD SHE DO THAT?
- I DON'T KNOW, SWEETIE.
SHE'S A COMPLICATED PERSON.
- WING AND WEI WILL NEVER
FORGIVE ME.
AND OPAL...
- YEAH, THEY MIGHT
TAKE SOME TIME TO COME AROUND,
BUT WE'LL WORK THROUGH IT
AS A FAMILY.
- DO YOU THINK THIS PLAN
WILL ACTUALLY WORK, SIR?
- I KNOW I CAN STOP
THE MECHA-SUITS
WITH AN ELECTROMAGNETIC PULSE,
SO IT STANDS TO REASON
THAT I CAN STOP
A GIANT MECHA-SUIT
WITH A GIANT
ELECTROMAGNETIC PULSE.
ZHU LI, I'VE BEEN THINKING.
- YOU'RE ALWAYS THINKING, SIR.
- YES, BUT LATELY, '
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT YOU.
I KNOW WE MIGHT NOT MAKE IT
OUT OF THIS MESS,
AND I FEEL LIKE THERE ARE SOME
THINGS I SHOULD TELL YOU.
- THERE ARE?
- I REMEMBER WHEN I WAS A BOY,
I HAD AN OSTRICH HORSE.
NAMED HER MRS. BEAKS.
I GREW UP ON A FARM.
DID I EVER
TELL YOU THAT, ZHU LI?
THIS WAS BEFORE THE CIRCUS
PEOPLE TOOK ME AWAY.
ANYWAY, I LOVED OLD MRS. BEAKS,
BUT I TOOK HER FOR GRANTED.
- YOU'LL HAVE TO FINISH
YOUR STORY LATER.
KUVIRA'S TROOPS ARE IN RANGE.
OKAY. I HOPE THIS WORKS.
[high-pitched buzzing]
[mechanical grinding]
[clanking and booming]
- YES! DEAD IN THEIR TRACKS.
OH, RATS.
SHE'S STILL COMING.
ZHU LI, DO THE THING!
- I'M AFRAID
THERE ARE NO MORE THINGS TO DO.
- WHAT WAS THAT?
- AN ELECTROMAGNETIC PULSE.
IT SHUT DOWN THE MECHA-SUITS,
BUT OUR POWER SOURCE IS FINE.
- LOCATE THE SOURCE
OF THE PULSE.
THAT MUST BE WHERE VARRICK IS.
THIRD AND FOURTH MECH PLATOONS,
MOVE IN AND CONTINUE THE SWEEP.
CAPTURE ANYONE LEFT
IN THIS CITY.
- VARRICK, HOW COME YOUR
ELECTRO-THINGY
SHUT DOWN THE SMALL MECHA-SUITS
BUT NOT THE BIG ONE?
- BECAUSE IT'S POWERED
WITH SPIRIT VINE ENERGY.
I'M SORRY.
I WISH I COULD HELP YOU,
BUT IT'S UNSTOPPABLE.
- IT'S NOT.
- DAD?
- I GOT HIM OUT OF JAIL
TO HELP.
I FIGURED
WE NEED ALL THE GENIUSES
WE CAN GET OUR HANDS
ON RIGHT NOW.
IF THE PRISON'S STILL STANDING
AFTER ALL THIS IS OVER,
WE CAN THROW HIM
BACK IN.
- I KNOW WHAT YOU ALL
MUST THINK OF ME,
BUT I LOVE REPUBLIC CITY,
AND I WOULD DO ANYTHING
TO SAVE HER.
- YOU THINK YOU KNOW
HOW TO DEFEAT THIS THING?
- YOU MUST ACT
LIKE AN INFECTION:
BREAK THE SKIN AND ATTACK
THE VITAL ORGANS.
DISCONNECT THE HEART
AND THE BRAIN,
AND THIS BEAST CANNOT LIVE.
- BUT HOW ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO GET INSIDE?
- FUTURE INDUSTRIES HAS PLASMA
SAWS FOR CUTTING PLATINUM.
IF WE HAD ONE
ON THE MECHA-SUIT...
- BUT THE SAWS ARE WAY TOO BIG.
WE'D NEVER GET THE SUITS
OFF THE GROUND.
- I THINK I CAN ADD
AN ELECTRICAL ELEMENT
TO THE WELDING TORCH
ON YOUR SUIT
AND CONVERT IT
INTO A PLASMA SAW.
THEN WE'LL JUST HAVE
TO LAND ON THE GIANT
AND CUT OPEN A HOLE BIG ENOUGH
FOR SOMEONE TO GET IN.
- LIKE A METAL MOSQUITO.
- YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
TO MOSQUITOES THAT LAND ON ME?
I SQUASH 'EM!
- WE'LL HAVE TO ATTACK
IN A SWARM
TO TRY TO KEEP YOU GUYS SAFE
IN THE HUMMINGBIRD SUITS.
IT LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE
OUR ONLY HOPE.
- ♪ OH, FIRST HE ATE THE FRUIT ♪
♪ THEN HE ATE THE LEAVES ♪
♪ HUNGRY LITTLE LEMUR
ATE UP ALL MY TREES ♪
OKAY.
GREAT JOB, EVERYBODY.
WHO'S GOT ANOTHER SONG FOR US?
- WE CAN'T JUST SIT AROUND HERE
SINGING OLD AIRBENDER SONGS
UNTIL WE'RE ALL CAPTURED
OR WORSE.
- SHOULD WE PLAY
THE BUTTON GAME?
WHO HAS A BUTTON?
[pounding]
WHERE DID THESE BADGERMOLES
COME FROM?
- THE ZOO!
MAKO ALWAYS HATED MY SINGING,
BUT THEY LOVE IT!
- WELL, WHAT ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO DO WITH BADGERMOLES?
- THEY'RE THE BEST
EARTHBENDERS AROUND!
WE CAN USE THEM TO TUNNEL
OUT OF THE CITY
WITHOUT KUVIRA'S TROOPS
SPOTTING US!
- ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS THE BEST PLAN?
LET'S FOLLOW THE MOLES!
- ♪ BADGERMOLES
DIGGING HOLES ♪
♪ UNDER REPUBLIC CITY ♪
♪ GOT TO RUN AWAY
FROM KUVIRA TODAY ♪
♪ ALTHOUGH I DO STILL
THINK SHE'S PRETTY ♪
[plodding]
- MECH PLATOONS, REPORT.
- THIRD PLATOON.
NO SIGN OF ANYONE SO FAR.
- FOURTH PLATOON.
EN ROUTE TO TRAIN STATION.
- I THINK WE FOUND THE SOURCE
OF THE ELECTROMAGNETIC PULSE:
FUTURE INDUSTRIES TOWER.
- THAT'S THE PLACE.
[mechanical buzzing]
- KUVIRA IS HEADED OUR WAY.
- HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
TO GET THE PLASMA SAWS READY?
- JUST A FEW MORE MINUTES.
- GET OUT THERE
AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
- IF YOU DO MANAGE
TO GET INSIDE,
FIND THE ENGINE ROOM.
THERE ARE TWO EMERGENCY LEVERS.
IF YOU SWITCH THEM OFF
AT THE SAME TIME,
YOU'LL CUT THE POWER.
- THANKS.
WE MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO BEAT THAT THING,
BUT WE CAN SLOW IT DOWN.
LET'S GO!
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[mechanical grinding]
[electrical booming]
[rocks clattering]
- [grunting]
[fluttering]
[electrical booming]
- JINORA!
- [grunting]
WHOA!
OOH!
- RAH!
- [gasps]
[crashing]
- ♪ OH, YIN ♪
♪ YOU'RE THE SWEETEST EVACUEE
I'VE EVER KNOWN ♪
♪ AND I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR BEING SO KIND ♪
♪ WHEN I WAS LIVING
IN YOUR HOME ♪
- HALT.
TURN AROUND SLOWLY,
AND PLEASE, STOP THAT SINGING.
YOU ARE ALL EARTH EMPIRE
PRISONERS.
COME WITH US AND NO ONE
WILL GET HURT.
- YOU DON'T NEED THESE PEOPLE.
THEY'RE JUST INNOCENT CIVILIANS
CAUGHT IN THE CROSSFIRE,
BUT I'M PRINCE WU, RIGHTFUL
LEADER OF THE EARTH KINGDOM.
TAKE ME TO KUVIRA.
I'VE GOT BUSINESS WITH HER.
- NO! DON'T DO IT, WU!
- I HAVE TO.
BUT BEFORE I GO, I'D LIKE
TO SING YOU A SONG.
♪ IF YOU DON'T RESPECT
THE BROACH ♪
♪ YOU DON'T RESPECT ME ♪
♪ OH, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO ♪
♪ YOU'RE NO BETTER
THAN A ROACH ♪
♪ BUT I'M ROYALTY ♪
♪ I GOT MY BADGERMOLES
WITH ME ♪
- ACTUALLY, YOUR SONG IS SO BAD,
YOUR BADGERMOLES DESERTED YOU.
- ♪ YOU DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT ♪
[booming]
[growling]
♪ OH, BADGERMOLES
I LOVE YOU, I LOVE YOU ♪
♪ I WANT TO, I WANT TO
PET YOUR SNOUTS ♪
HA-HA!
[cheers]
[electrical humming]
[clanking]
- IF WE STOP THAT MECHA-GIANT,
IT WILL ALL BE BECAUSE OF YOU.
- YOU'RE THE ONE WHO DESIGNED
THESE INCREDIBLE SUITS.
IT'S GREAT TO BE WORKING
TOGETHER AGAIN.
- I LOVE YOU, DAD.
- I LOVE YOU, TOO.
- ZHU LI?
- YES?
- [gulps]
I HAVE SOMETHING
I NEED TO ATTACH
BEFORE WE TAKE OFF.
- ATTACH TO WHAT?
- I NEED TO ATTACH THIS RING
TO YOUR FINGER.
ZHU LI MOON,
WILL YOU DO THE THING
FOR THE REST OF OUR LIVES?
- YES.
- YES!
NOW, LET'S GO ATTACH THESE
BARELY-FUNCTIONAL RUST BUCKETS
TO A GIANT
KILLER SMASHING MACHINE!
- IT'S EXACTLY HOW I ALWAYS
PICTURED OUR ENGAGEMENT.
[distant fluttering]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- AIM FOR THAT SPOT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE BACK,
THE ONE I CAN NEVER REACH.
- GOT IT.
- WHAA! LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[electrical buzzing]
WOW!
I WISH I HAD THAT KIND
OF FLEXIBILITY.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[beeping]
- HANG ON!
- AH!
[explosion]
- I NEED MORE POWER!
THEY'RE CUTTING IN!
MORE POWER!
[mechanical grinding]
[cracking]
- WE NEED TO GET OUT OF HERE.
- ALMOST THERE.
- [gasps]
- WE HAVE TO GO NOW!
- ALMOST THERE. ALMOST THERE.
- DAD! NOW!
- GOOD-BYE, ASAMI.
I LOVE YOU.
- DAD!
- HIROSHI'S PLAN WORKED.
THERE'S OUR OPENING.
- [grunting]