- Donna: Is it alive?
- Haley: Mommy, is it okay?
Joanie:
Mommy, fix it.
Make it better.
Girls, girls,
Mommy's gonna be
right back, okay?
Haley:
Why don't
its wings work?
Gordon,
is it breathing?
Barely.
Brian:
Yeah, watch out
for mites.
Well, is there
something we can do?
- Give it some water, or...
- I think we're beyond that.
( sighs )
I should take it
to the vet.
Honey, the girls
have to get to school.
And with your car
in the shop...
Yeah, yeah,
you're right.
Hey, you need
a ride, neighbor?
Donna:
Oh, that would be
so great.
- Yeah, thanks, Brian.
- Hey, no problemo.
Poor little sucker.
Let go, let God,
right?
Hey, man.
Don't sweat today.
You can do this.
( chirping )
( loud whirring )
"Are 'Friends' Electric?"
playing in background
♪ You know I hate to ask ♪
♪ But are "friends"
electric? ♪
♪ Only mine's broke down ♪
♪ And now
I've no one to love ♪
♪ Mm, mm-mm, mm-mm... ♪
Look, it's not
your fault.
It's no one's fault.
It's like when you get
an early snow
and it freezes
your orange grove.
And then the farmer
has to find
another way
to deliver the juice.
Even if every snowflake
is totally unique like you.
( door opens )
- Gordon, what the hell?
- You're my 11:45.
You got us milling
around out there like
a bunch of Frenchmen.
Randy,
I'm with someone.
Randy: I'll wait
in line for a Ferris wheel.
I'll wait in line for a beer.
But damned
if I'll wait around
till 11:45 to get fired
by flipping you
or flipping Joe MacMillan.
Wait, you're firing me?
I'm being fired?
- Just calm down.
- My reference letter.
And don't worry,
I wrote it myself.
Sign it.
Oh, my God,
I gotta call Patty.
Randy:
And can I just say
on behalf
of a once-great company,
I look forward
to driving past here
when the "For Lease" signs
get nailed to the lawn
and your little
PC vision quest
crashes and burns.
( theme music playing )
28 pounds.
That's not portable,
that's luggable.
And those are
the combined sales figures
for Coleco, Vectrex,
and Atari.
- Video games.
- Microcomputers.
Proof that America
wants these machines
in their homes.
And how did
the PC business respond?
With a cassette deck,
a sewing machine,
and a carburetor.
We're not making
a carburetor.
We're making this.
By the end of this year,
Cardiff Electric will release
to the market
a truly portable computer
with two disk drives,
integrated screen,
and keyboard,
weighing no more
than 15 pounds.
( laughter, chatter )
Anyone that knows anything
about microprocessing...
You've got
that number wrong,
right, Gordon?
It's gonna take
a million dollars
and four times the size
of this desk...
- Yes, that's correct.
- ( chatter stops )
It's ambitious.
You know who was good
with screens?
- Randy.
- Sure was.
Say, where is Randy?
Oh, that's right,
you fired him.
Run out to the parking lot.
Maybe you can flag him down.
- Gordon, outside.
- Brian: Guys, relax.
Man:
No, I'm not relaxing.
Wake up, Brian.
We used to build products
that people would buy.
We're not even
in reality anymore.
- Listen--
- Larry, we're dealing with--
( door closes )
These are the guys
you chose?
After I let go
of 46 people this morning,
something I'm in no way
qualified to do.
I'm worried
about their attitude.
Their attitude is based
on the laws of physics,
which, if I were you,
I'd bone up on.
You're looking
at our only engineers
with any microprocessor
experience at all.
They're what's left,
so, yeah, these are my guys.
"Advice" playing
on headphones
♪ They tell you
you're a mess ♪
how to dress ♪
♪ They tell you
what you've found ♪
about your sound ♪
♪ Advice,
and it's good for you ♪
I don't need your ♪
- ♪ Advice... ♪
- Hey.
♪ And they tell you
how to wear your hair ♪
how to care... ♪
- Hey.
- ♪ And they tell you
how to live your life... ♪
You could at least wait
until we've left the building.
( yells )
Oh, thank you!
♪ You can screw
your advice ♪
♪ They tell you
everything's okay ♪
♪ And they tell you
to live their way ♪
about what's right ♪
♪ And they tell you
about white might, advice ♪
♪ It's good for you,
advice ♪
♪ I don't need
your advice ♪
♪ You can screw
your advice... ♪
( mutters )
( keyboard clicking )
♪ Advice, it's good
for you, advice ♪
♪ I don't need
your advice ♪
♪ You can screw
♪ Advice. ♪
Where do we put
the heat sink?
Well, we run it
at four megahertz,
maybe we don't need one.
No, it's too slow.
Craig James was slow
compared to Dickerson.
Still plenty
fast enough.
There's gotta be a way
to add speed without
adding heat.
Or you can build in a griddle
and fry steaks on it.
What do you want to
call this place?
I guess "Skunk Works"
is taken.
"The Chamber
of Chipsets."
"Logic Lair."
We're probably gonna
end up killing each other
in here and ourselves.
Well, let's call it
"The Kill Room."
Man:
Not bad.
Joe:
So he uses the collateral
to repay the money
he borrowed
to purchase the target.
Pretty brilliant,
right?
( laughs )
- Who the hell's that?
- Aaron Littlefield,
Eiger &amp; Littlefield
Venture Capital.
"Venture capital"?
Hell, I remember
when it was still
called "money."
Give him five minutes.
He just flew in from New York.
- Sorry, I already had lunch.
- So did we.
They keep reading about
the Silicon Prairie
in the "Journal."
They have cash to spend
and they want exposure
to this market.
Our PC could be
a nice entry point.
You know I gotta clear
all this with Nathan.
I already have.
- Aaron.
- Hey.
Hey, John Bosworth here.
Nice to meet ya.
- How was the flight?
- Oh, a little bumpy,
but worth it.
Well, good.
I sure as shit hope so.
I've identified
the bugs in the PCBs.
We're gonna have to
recall about 10,000 units.
But the bigger problem
is with the keyboard bouncing.
If we could just
redesign the trim,
then--
But that's not
our purview, right?
How soon can I
tell Mark?
Monday, Tuesday
at the latest.
- Your folks are well?
- Oh, great. Thank you.
Only parents I ever knew
who came to the game to
cheer on the xylophonist.
( laughs )
And how's Martine?
Well, she thought
that Texas Instruments
meant staying in Texas.
This is our third stop
in five years, so...
I think she wants
to settle down, but--
But that's not the way
you climb the ladder.
( chuckles )
I can't believe
we're talking like this--
climbing ladders,
quarterly targets.
We are a long way
from high school.
Oh, well, thank God.
My hair and that band uniform.
Hey, we all knew that you
weren't cut out for band.
You were just
marking time,
waiting for something
better to come along.
Donna...
not to be a pain,
but I'm meeting
with Mark tomorrow
and that report
would be helpful.
Oh, okay.
You'll have it.
( groans )
( wheels squeaking )
( clicks )
( rings )
Mr. MacMillan's office.
Hi...
Debbie:
Cameron?
We have got
an ideal business climate.
Unlimited growth curve.
And you just got your
ass handed to you by IBM.
They took their shot.
They missed.
But the cash from
your system packages
is running out, correct?
Guys, I'm gonna
find out anyway.
- John: How's that?
- Well, we partner with you,
we audit your books
top to bottom,
install upper
management on-site,
probably Roger.
- You'd report to him.
- Roger?
It's just an option
we're discussing.
- At lunch?
- Aaron: That's right.
You know, maybe instead
of sending someone out,
you do a weekly call.
Guys, I haven't even heard
a rollout date yet, okay?
What's your marketing strategy?
How do you plan on rebuilding
your client base here?
We got a whole new
client base.
Yeah, Joe here
wants to take this
machine to the people.
Yeah, no more biz-to-biz.
We're pushing doorbells
and pounding pavement.
Along with a sophisticated
media campaign.
Oh, sophisticated, my ass.
Come on, Joe.
We're tired of
these doodad launches
and corporate suites.
No, I wanna
breathe me some air.
You know,
mom-and-pop stores,
county fairs.
Now, we may not have
the track record
or the balance sheet,
but, by God,
we got heart.
That can-do
Texas spirit, y'all.
My home number's
on the back.
I want you to call
the ranch anytime.
Sure will.
Let me show you
some sketches.
It's so good
seeing you again, Joe.
I'll be in touch.
( softly )
What do you think?
Let 'em go?
What, before midnight?
You can't win a race
at the quarter pole.
Seriously,
buy yourself some
goodwill with these guys.
( loudly )
All right, thanks,
everyone.
Have a good night.
Brian: Especially if we try
and cram a bigger motherboard
into a smaller case.
Either way, we swap out
the crystal and we
overclock the CPU.
Which heats up
the innards, which means
a bigger heat sink.
And may I remind you,
we just ditched
the heat sink.
( sighs )
Okay.
Hey, how's it
going?
- No contact, remember?
- I know, I know.
- Look, I don't mean to pry.
- ( soda can clatters )
I know it's only been a week
and you're under a lot
of pressure,
but if you could
just give us
some sort
of idea as to--
I'll order
a pizza.
She took my soda.
Nothing like a bubble bath
to make you forget life's
little traumas.
- Works for me.
- Oh, we also got them
a little something.
Oh, you
shouldn't have.
"Bowser"?
It's not exactly
a bird's name.
( scoffs )
Poor thing's dead by now.
I expect you can call it
whatever you like.
( tinny music playing )
Is that Chopin's
"Funeral March"?
The Japanese never sleep.
Look here.
It's our back pager
this month.
Your father thinks
we'll move half a million.
( chuckles )
"No-doubt" Dad.
It's a catalogue
business, darling.
Both:
"There's always doubt."
Now, don't go telling
Gordon it's from us.
I know he
doesn't approve.
( water sloshing )
He working late?
He's got a new project.
Well, make sure he does
the dishes sometime.
I love
my son-in-law,
but I don't
wanna see you
worn down to a nub.
Why, do I seem
nubbish to you?
You are radiant,
as always.
( girls giggling )
How's life at TI?
You know, we haven't even
seen Hunt at the club
since he moved back.
Well, nose
to the grindstone.
Well, maybe Fourth of July,
he'll show off that foreign
wife of his.
- Mom, she's Canadian.
- She is a guest
of this country.
She can wave a flag
and light something on fire
like the rest of us.
Well, I don't think
they'll be in Dallas long.
If management likes him,
they'll probably ship him
overseas.
Mm, old Hunt in Vienna
or Rome, Italy.
Can you imagine?
- This is very nice.
- Mm-hmm, a man needs
to seek shelter.
I believe we
have that in common.
We don't just need money.
We need smart money.
A name. Someone
who puts us on the map.
Yeah, I know.
You weren't wrong
to do what you did,
but then,
neither was John.
John:
Hey.
A little scotch here,
and... I guessed.
We let you in the door,
Joe, we gave you the rope.
But only one
boss-dick can swing it.
Now, you're the vision guy
and I'm retired and I want
to stay retired.
The way that works
is that John here
sends me my checks,
keeps me
fat and happy.
So John makes
the financial decisions
on this project,
all of them.
Agreed.
Good.
( chuckles )
No more backstage
bullshit.
I'm gonna set you up
with Louise Lutherford.
- An old friend of ours.
- Cardiff: Mm-hmm,
she is a handful...
but she's got
more than enough capital
to see us through.
And she's local,
so no "Rogers."
Yeah, that's
all well and good,
but does she have
a background in--
Good evening, Seth.
Mr. Cardiff.
Are we dining tonight?
Oh, you know it.
I'll have the petit fillet.
Burn it,
and peas and mash.
Porterhouse, rare.
Rare.
I'll have the same.
I mean, we could
recess the keyboard
in the bottom cover
and run the connector cable
through the hinges.
Okay.
No one's ever
done that before.
- Well, does that mean
it can't be done?
- No, just expensive.
Well, how else
are we gonna make room
for the screen?
Gordon, I'm not trying
to yuck your yum here.
No one
wants this to work
more than me.
It's a hell of a concept,
but to execute it...
- ...that's tough sleddin'.
- I know, I know.
( sighs )
First thing tomorrow,
we sit down with Joe,
bring him back to Earth,
tell him it can't be done.
I'll fly wingman
if you want.
No, no,
I'll tell him.
( grunts )
- ( phone rings )
- What?
Joe:
You called earlier.
No, I don't--
yes, fine, yes,
I did by mistake.
What?
What do you want?
Just checking in.
Okay, I'm all checked.
- I just wanted to know...
- What's taking so long?
You're a talented coder,
but right now you're
a bottleneck.
( groans )
Have you considered
motivational speaking?
'Cause you've got a gift, man.
Seriously, sign me up.
Send me the tapes.
Do I need
to come down there?
No.
- Then I guess I'll--
- See ya.
( line clicks )
( sighs )
( groans )
Sorry I missed
your mother.
- No, you're not.
- ( clicking )
Gordon:
At least the bird's gone.
The girls were so upset,
they barely ate.
Yeah?
Maybe not the best
night for chicken.
So, how much longer,
do you think?
( sighs )
Couple hours.
That's
an interesting layout.
If I can
make it all fit.
- Can you take a--
- No, Gordon, I have
to finish this.
You're right,
you're right.
I'm sorry.
( clicking continues )
- Well, you know
what you could do?
- What?
You could move
the interrupt controller
and then maybe scootch
those parity RAM chips down.
- Do you mind if I--
- No, no, no.
- All yours.
- Here and here.
Then if you rotate
these DMA controllers
to make room,
you can...
Wait, wait,
wait, what?
Piggyback it.
- Software comes and goes...
- Hardware is forever.
Okay.
Okay, okay,
that's interesting.
"Germ Free Adolescence"
playing on headphones
♪ He's a germ-free
adolescent ♪
♪ Cleanliness
is her obsession ♪
♪ Cleans her teeth
10 times a day ♪
♪ Scrub away, scrub away
scrub away ♪
♪ The S.R. way ♪
♪ You may
get to touch her... ♪
( music stops )
( object clicks )
( drawer thumps )
Hi.
Those Lloyd's shoes?
Who the hell's Lloyd?
Come on.
Lloyd... one hell
of a bowler.
Good Lutheran,
three kids.
I had to fire him
this morning.
You think
it's a good idea
walking around
in a dead man's shoes?
Where are you headed,
young lady?
This is your first job, huh?
Am I right?
You're already rooting around
the offices after hours?
I heard money's
tight around here.
I thought I'd switch
off your light.
Uh-huh.
( chuckles )
Hey, what is the difference
between "Go To" and "Go Sub"?
Oh, "Go To"
executes the next line.
"Go Sub," you need, like,
a return command at the end.
That makes
no sense to me.
Yeah, it's hard
at the beginning.
- ( sighs )
- ( glasses clatter )
- If it weren't
for your friend Joe...
- ( boot unzips )
I'd be home right now.
- ( boot zipper whines )
- He's different, huh?
Joe?
( chuckles )
You take care
of those shoes.
And, Cameron?
You can work here
as late as you'd like.
You cannot live here.
I think we can
make this work.
If we actually
split the motherboard
and then layer
one half on top
of the other,
run the jumpers
vertically.
So you're doubling
the amount of chips
on each half.
- Yeah.
- Interesting.
Where'd you get
that idea?
In my kitchen.
It'd buy us a couple
centimeters, for sure.
- Nice work.
- If we can stabilize
the vertices.
Hey, why don't you let it
ride for a cycle, Stan?
Donna drove me in
this morning, but I'm
gonna need a ride home.
What's this?
Gordon:
It's our new motherboard.
Brian:
Buddy, I thought
we had one.
Not like this.
I call it a layered array.
It's really,
really different.
- What it is is--
- Yeah, I see that.
Who's gonna mass-produce
a brand-new board from scratch?
You think Intel or AMD
is gonna reroute
their entire
assembly lines for us?
For Cardiff Electric?
Is that reasonable?
I mean, what
are we doing here?
You're right.
I wasn't thinking
that far ahead.
- I just--
- Gordo, it's
a killer idea, it is.
But we got three months.
Every bone in my body
is telling me
that if we try
and reinvent the wheel here,
man, we're gonna end up
with a square wheel.
But, hey,
it's your call.
( sighs )
Forget it, guys.
- Let's go back to alpha.
- Larry: What? Are you kidding?
I'll tell Joe.
( whirring, grinding )
( cracks )
( whirrs )
( groans )
( clatters )
( thumps )
"First Time" playing
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ It's my first time, oh ♪
♪ Please be kind, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Don't hurt me, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
You gonna eat
all that yourself?
You gonna try
and take it from me?
I'm Judie, this is Ajax
and his asshole friend.
- Ajax: Hey.
- Friend: Hey, yo.
- Cameron.
- Does Cameron have money?
Does it have
an automobile?
You mean a car?
No.
- You live around here?
- Uh, no, I work, like,
a mile that way.
Work? Like, a job?
The day I sell out
and get a job is
the day I die.
Materialistic
greed hamsters
spinning their wheels.
- Oh, says the guy
who wants a car.
- ( laughs )
Come nightfall
we're gonna head up
to Yuppie Row
and tag the living crap
out of it.
Until then
we're just gonna
hole up here, you know,
thrash a bit,
pound some vodka.
Thing is,
we're short on vodka.
So, you're just gonna
hang out here till then?
Yeah, you got
a better idea?
Actually, yeah.
Directions
to Ms. Lutherford's.
Cocktails at 5:30,
dinner at 6:00.
Well, money's
money, right?
Uh-huh.
( door closes )
It's okay,
you can go on in.
- John: Loulu.
- Louise: John.
You look wonderful.
Let me introduce you here
to Joe MacMillan.
- Of course, Joseph.
- Joe MacMillan, Loulu.
Travis,
Joe MacMillan here.
So, Joseph,
where do you hail from?
- Hudson River Valley.
- Oh, I adore that area.
- You get to the city?
- Yes, often.
Travis and I
go annually.
He ignores the opera,
I sponsor it.
Last season,
we saw "Figaro."
How'd that turn out?
Same way
it always does, John.
It's 200 years old.
But I do hate when they
try to force that poor boy
to marry his own mother.
Of course.
He owes her money.
( both chuckle )
John, I believe
you brought a shark
to my table.
No, dear.
Just a deal.
Yes, yes.
Nathan mentioned it.
I did a little
research of my own.
I will take 80%
of your PC project
for $10 million.
That's a little
aggressive.
John, IBM has
poisoned your well.
I know
I'm not the first name
on Nathan Cardiff's Rolodex,
which means your cash flow
is a little stopped up,
kind of like
my second husband's aorta.
Our projected earnings
are many multiples of that.
If there's a better deal
for you elsewhere, you are
welcome to take it.
Y'all excuse us?
- This is insane.
- Keep your voice down.
At that price,
we're better off
going to the banks
or selling to Tandy.
All right, let me
talk her off the ledge.
This person knows
nothing about our machine.
She'll wrap it in velvet,
call it "Bonnie Blue,"
and we won't
be able to stop her.
Hey, partner,
we're already there.
Joseph,
is everything all right?
( bell ringing )
Oh, glorious.
Dinner's served.
- He's on the call.
- With Mark?
Oh, God. Maybe
I could just sneak in
and hand it to him.
- I wouldn't.
- I could just--
Mark, you know that
and I know that,
but how can we get
Somerville on board?
Well, I'm doing
everything I can.
"We Got Your Money"
playing in background
♪ I want to be
a problem, oh ♪
♪ I want to make
a scene, oh ♪
♪ I want
to get reactions, oh ♪
♪ And wake you
from your dream, oh ♪
♪ I don't care
if you don't like it, oh ♪
♪ Or you think
that it's the best, oh ♪
♪ As long
as you remember, oh ♪
♪ And then we're up
with all the rest, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
- ♪ I would like... ♪
- Ow.
What's your job
all about?
Software.
Oh, yeah.
I think my dad
does something like that.
I think.
Grimace!
♪ And to all
you frat boys, oh... ♪
Tip the mamacita.
( Judie giggles )
Hey, Cam.
This ink's
got your name on it.
Here.
Got a good idea.
Judie:
Yeah, do it up. Whoo!
Come here.
Come on, Cam.
Let's print it.
Now, just trust me.
I got it.
John:
He says to her,
"Absolutely not."
And she says, "Henry, we are
flying a woman into orbit
on the space shuttle.
All's I'm askin'
is for you to take me to--
oh, oh, oh, Omaha!"
( laughing )
Stop, you're so bad.
So, Joseph,
what do we think?
- About Omaha?
- About the space program,
Miss Sally Ride.
It's a gimmick.
You're not proud of NASA
for breaking the gender barrier?
The Soviets
did it-- twice.
So it's first
or not at all?
Curious outlook for someone
who's cloning an IBM.
Now, now, go easy
on him, Loulu.
He's a Yankee.
( laughs )
Sorry.
Getting into bed
with you boys.
Least I can do
is check the sheets
and fluff the pillows.
( chuckles )
Isn't that right,
Travis?
We're not
gonna be partners.
Why's that?
Because you're a bored,
poisonous dilettante
with time on her hands
and no taste.
Two things
destroy companies,
Ms. Lutherford--
mediocrity and making it
about yourself.
I think you make
everything about yourself.
That's why you
rent your friends
and repel everyone else.
Boz, we have
a deal or not?
I'll have Barry
draw up the papers.
There, you see?
Joseph, it's not hard.
It's just knowing
your side of the saddle.
More wine?
Oh, Travis,
bring us some brandy.
We're celebrating.
"Take It Now"
playing in background
- Yo, Cam, let me finish.
- No.
( sighs, mutters )
( groans )
- ( groans )
- ( lipstick clatters )
I don't know jack squat
about brandy.
( clatters )
Fantastic meringue.
What took you
so long?
It's too late
for brandy.
It's not brandy.
Tuke Holdsworth, 1912.
"Stabat Mater"
playing in background
We decided
on a port.
John:
I'll take a snort.
Give her a pop,
Travis.
( cork pops )
That pig-iron bitch
had us right where
she wanted us
and she kicked us
to the curb.
- Hell, we had a deal.
- We don't need her.
- You tell Nathan that.
- We jump-start the project,
crush the timetable
from six months
down to three.
Build the prototype
on our own dime,
then show investors
when we have leverage.
- ( engine starts )
- What'd you say to her?
Hey, hey.
What'd you do?
We'll talk tomorrow.
And this sumbitch,
I know he's gonna
cash the heart ace
and take
the diamond finesse.
Instead, he discards
spade from the dummy
and plays the queen.
( laughs )
I'm like, "Neville,
are you a Redskins fan?"
You know?
Hey, man,
are you all right?
I'm telling you,
you oughta think
about joining
'cause I'm getting tired
of carrying cards
for these damn Yanks
and mackerel snappers.
- Whoa, whoa!
- ( bangs )
( tires squealing )
( both panting )
Ow.
Aw, man.
Oh.
Are you all right?
Oh, thank Christ.
I mean, I told Vicky
they have got to
trim those branches.
How are you supposed
to see cross traffic
when the sidewalk's
a damn jungle?
You're fired.
( chuckles )
What?
You're fired.
( doorbell rings )
The address calculation code.
It's too long.
It takes up
too many bytes.
What I need is some way
of grabbing the addresses
without telling the CPU
where to look for them,
like an address book
that's also a map.
Cameron...
why are you here?
I'm stuck.
( sighs )
( taps )
( bird chirping )
Another late night, huh?
- Gordon, you're bleeding.
- Shh, shh, shh.
- You hear that?
- ( chirping continues )
It's alive.
( chirping continues )
I called Animal Control.
They said the kindest thing
is to just kill it.
- Maybe you could--
- Look, Donna, I'm not
going back out there.
- I've had kind of a day.
- Okay--
I'm gonna take off my shoes,
kiss the girls,
and wash up, all right?
( chirping continues )
( sighs )
"We Got Your Money"
playing
♪ I want to be
a problem, oh ♪
♪ I want to make
a scene, oh ♪
♪ I want
to get reactions, oh ♪
♪ And wake you
from your dream, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Oh! ♪