$1.3 million
in 20 days and you just--
you just understand?
The future's expensive.
We knew that.
Apple spends that daily
on its in-house catering.
Apple ships PCs
that you can type on,
that have screens.
Oh, and what is--
is that a fish tank?
Joe: Yes and no.
It's actually
a time machine.
See, to test
the BIOS and hardware
at the speed
we're gunning for,
we need the 12
and a half megahertz 286,
but it's not out yet.
We only have the eight,
and if we overclock
the eight-- pfft--
- the chip will fry in seconds,
so Larry here--
- Stan.
Stan's put the chip
in mineral oil and
cranked down the temp.
Cooling it makes it run
at 12 and a half megahertz,
- so we get to design tomorrow
before tomorrow's even here.
- Well, what's taking so long?
We're right on track
to have our prototype
ready for COMDEX.
- In November.
- Oh, and, hey,
look at this, look at this.
Three four-layer PCBs.
That's the new norm.
Our PC's aiming for 12.
So, imagine, um,
an invisible subway system
with electrons as trains.
More layers,
fewer collisions,
which is pretty amazing
when you're moving at
the speed of light.
The electrons
actually move at one third
the speed of light.
Bigger point here, Stan,
please stop talking.
The checks you're writing
are making innovation happen.
Tell me that's
not beautiful,
that you don't feel
the excitement.
I will "feel
the excitement"
when a clone with our logo
encased in fancy plastic
running Lotus 1-2-3
is on the shelves
over at Sears
and people are shoving
each other out the way
to get to it
with their wallets
hanging open.
I imagine
how you must feel.
It's difficult
to believe in something
when your knowledge
is so limited.
Maylene:
Nathan Cardiff's
on the line.
- ( computer beeps )
- Mother Mary.
396 milliseconds.
- Hot damn!
- Don't screw with us.
- Are you sure you ran it right?
- Checked it three times.
- Where's Gordon?
- He might still be sleeping.
Yes, I will be home
for bedtimes.
I know I said that last night,
but tonight I promise.
Hey, little privacy.
396 milliseconds.
What?
But she's not done.
She did the subroutine
for the hard drive table
lookups first.
That's what the seeks
clocked in at.
Donna, we just hit
the Doherty Threshold.
No, I know.
I know. I love you.
"I Love Your Neurosis"
playing in background
We hit
the Doherty Threshold.
Someone's been
up late studying.
Maybe between mocking me
and your 19th orange soda,
you could register
a little happiness.
I knew
it would be fast.
- How much longer
till you're done?
- I don't know, two days?
A day and a night,
or two full days?
31.29 hours
and 13 nanoseconds.
Can you leave
and shut the door?
I'm calling
a team-building meeting.
( scoffs )
You're joking, right?
Joe:
All right, gather round,
come closer.
Today, we hit a milestone.
When engineers measure
the speed of a PC,
they talk
about something called
the "Doherty Threshold
of System Response Time."
It sounds fancy,
I know,
but, basically,
what it means is
when you ask your computer
to do something
and hit the enter key,
if it answers you back
in less than 400 milliseconds,
just under
half a second,
then you will stay glued
to that machine for hours.
Your eyes may glaze over,
but your productivity
will soar.
You'll be transfixed,
mesmerized.
Even a slight deviation
back to half a second
response time
will allow your attention
to stray.
You'll get up
and do the dishes,
pick up the remote,
watch the game.
But under 400 milliseconds,
ah, that's the sweet spot.
Well, guess what?
Our soon-to-be Cardiff PC,
though it looks ragtag now,
just clocked in
at 396 milliseconds.
( clapping )
Joe:
Once assembled,
it will not only
be faster than other PCs
on the market,
it will also be
addictive.
So spend time
with your families, folks,
get drinks with your friends,
'cause once our PC hits,
you're gonna be hanging
out with it.
- ( scattered laughing )
- And, hey, Debbie,
let's see 'em.
Now, this is just
a smattering of the calls
I'm getting now.
Potential customers,
retailers,
and they all wanna know
what we're up to.
And tomorrow
a reporter from the
"Wall Street Quarterly"
is coming
to do a story on us.
Practically begged me
to get in the door.
We're hitting
the radar, people.
I mean, really
cooking with gas.
So it's only
appropriate...
- Barry: No, no, no, no.
You'll contaminate.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Everybody disperse.
- Joe, what are you doing?
- Ed: Get that thing outta here.
- Stan: You could blow
the whole thing.
- Barry: Come on, Joe.
- Relax.
No one goes anywhere.
( chuckles )
Oh, that's what I call
cooking the books!
( clapping,
laughter )
( theme music playing )
No, Daddy,
my pink ones.
Haley, stop.
These are pink enough.
Your pinks
are dirty, sweetie.
Apple slices
and peanut butter?
Joanie:
Yuck, they turn brown!
( singsong )
Not if I put lemon juice.
Just wear the red ones,
Haley.
Why is it that
when Mommy says,
"Wear the socks,"
- you suddenly
wear the socks?
- Donna: Gordon.
All right, Smooch,
go put your shoes on.
"Sett of Ayers"
playing on radio
Maybe we should start
smoking pot again.
That'd take off
the edge.
Yeah, and we'd never
get out of bed.
How can you listen to this
so early in the morning?
- Doesn't it get
on your nerves?
- ( music stops )
So, 2:15, don't forget.
At the playground, not
the traffic circle.
Huh?
You're picking up the girls.
You'll have them till 6:00.
That's right.
- Wait, can't you just--
- No, no, I can't.
Hunt's been covering for me
way too much lately.
I can't be late
with this one.
- Well, what about your mom?
- They're in Vegas, I told you.
And Rose has
the chicken pox.
Do you listen?
Fine, I blanked.
2:15 it is.
Thank you.
But please come home
right after.
I'm gonna have to
go back to the office.
Haley threw my toothbrush
in the toilet with pee pee
in it.
I'm handling
food here.
All right, come on.
Let's get the pee pee
toothbrush out.
What did you do to her?
What did you say?
( music resumes )
( sprinkler hissing )
( engine starts )
Hi!
Gordon, hey,
don't work too hard!
"Too Political"
playing in background
♪ It's disgusting and sick
and always has been ♪
♪ Liberators become
oppressors all over again ♪
♪ And the church
stands on its wealth
as it blesses the troops ♪
♪ Telling them
that their way is so true ♪
♪ And they build ghettos
to put their prisoners in ♪
♪ Still building ghettos
♪ No more ghettos! ♪
- Mornin'.
- ( sighs )
I got donuts.
I put 'em in the break room.
I don't want
that fancy reporter thinking
we ain't got no hospitality.
( sighs )
You all right?
I think I need
your help.
Okay.
Getting an article about us
in the "Wall Street Quarterly,"
the right article,
that could be a game-changer,
put our PC on the map,
take this company into
the stratosphere,
but if we seem sloppy
or fly-by-night,
if we project the wrong image,
then it could all fall apart.
Should I have gotten
pastries instead?
No, those are fine.
( whispering )
Our real problem is Cameron.
Her work station's
a pigsty.
It's unprofessional,
it's unsanitary.
Frankly,
it's embarrassing.
We've gotta get it cleaned up
before Kane gets here.
Well, he's scheduled
for 11:00.
Yeah, tell
the cleaning crew
to hurry.
But she'll
never let 'em.
You know
how she is.
Yeah.
You live
close to here, right?
Yeah, just
down on Buxton.
Then convince her
to go back to your place
for a break.
Get her to take a shower,
wash her hair.
She doesn't hate you
and might listen.
You know,
woman to woman or...
Well, you're her boss.
Can't you talk to her?
I can't tell her
to put on a bra, Debbie.
You can.
And please do.
Okay.
I'll do my best.
Oh, thank you.
Cardiff:
You get enough
of Milly's sausage?
Another bite
and I'd, hell,
pop like a mosquito
sucking a pig.
Good as ever, though.
She is somethin'.
Yep, she's a keeper.
Like they say, John,
"Good help is hard to find."
Yeah, well, thanks
for breakfast, Nathan.
I guess I'd best
be getting on back to it.
To what?
Beg your pardon?
What's your rush?
Thought Joe MacMillan
had everything pretty
much in hand.
( groans )
You know what
I just can't shake?
Loulu not funding
our PC pipe dream,
that I get.
She's a tough one.
But her not
returning my calls
after three weeks?
- Joe called
that woman names--
- Bullshit.
- He wouldn't--
You could call Loulu
a redneck sack of goat sperm.
She'd still do business
with you if she thought
she could make a buck.
Is that your new M.O.?
I ask a question,
first thing you say is,
"Joe..."?
Ah, come--
no, of course not.
I want
a straight answer.
Who's running things?
I am.
You better be
'cause folks are
starting to talk.
They're saying that
you're letting this thing
run away from ya.
Make clear who's
working for who
or else we're both
gonna look like idiots.
All right, I think
you know your way out.
( groans )
( gunshot blasts )
And with this extra-wide
chip carrier,
the CPU and coprocessor
can be clipped into
a single ribbon cable.
It's just one of the many
innovations that helped us
hit the Doherty Threshold.
( scoffs )
You're not
an engineer, are ya?
What?
You just sound
a bit canned, that's all.
Like you're repeating
what people told you
or getting it from books.
( chuckles )
No, I'm the product manager.
- Do I have a degree in--
- I mean, the Doherty Threshold?
Come on.
You know how many companies
think they hit that
in the testing phase?
All of them.
Try building the damn thing
with the heat sink
and the case.
Once the realities
of physics kick in,
it's a whole new ball game.
Not to mention I don't write
for "Hobbyists' Weekly."
My readers
will be asleep in seconds.
- Okay, fair enough.
- Joe, I told you on the phone,
I came here because
Matt Garrison in New York
said he owed you a favor.
I owed him one,
so I said I'd pop by,
but now I gotta go.
Ron, please, please.
Just meet some of our people,
get their stories.
There's
an underdog angle here
I guarantee
you'll find interesting.
- Fine. 15 minutes.
- Great.
"Learn to Hate the 80s"
playing in background"
( keyboard keys clicking )
As you can see,
we don't waste money
on amenities
because, hey,
you know programmers.
What's the joke?
"They're just machines
for turning pizza into code."
Yeah, good one.
But Cameron,
in this case, is a girl.
Yep, you don't
see that every day.
22, brilliant,
and writing a BIOS
that defies belief.
- What happened?
- Cameron: It's gone.
All my code, I--
Did you try
booting it up again?
I can't even
get a prompt.
All right, look, it's
probably just the monitor
or the connection.
- Guys...
- What-- what's happening?
You backed it up, right?
Yeah-- yeah,
at some point.
"At some point"?
What's that?
- What the...? Oh, no.
- ( Gordon scoffs )
Are you kidding me?
Guys, it was a power surge.
Probably just
burned out the disks.
Where are your
backup floppies?
She left one in the A-drive.
It's toast.
FAT's gotta be empty.
Cameron, where
are the other ones?
- Here, check 'em.
- Yep.
( keys clicking )
( whimpers )
No.
- This one's degaussed.
- This one, too-- wiped.
What?
How is that possible?
A vacuum cleaner?
- You plugged your vacuum
cleaner in my computer?!
- Okay, okay.
- Janitor: Sorry, sorry!
- Just walk me through
what happened.
You put your--
you put your backups
next to your speakers
and then you blast music?
Good God, Cameron.
- Why didn't you just put
a magnet up to them?
- Get off!
Hey, calm down!
Who the hell
is this?
Ron Kane,
"Wall Street Quarterly."
Okay, girls. Let's go.
Let's go see your dad.
Daddy!
You're late. Miss Ferris
had to call Mommy.
I know, I know.
I know.
I asked you to do one thing.
You can't write it on your arm?
You can't get an admin
to remind you?
Things got crazy, okay?
I'm having kind of a day here.
Oh, you're having
kind of a day?
Now I'm gonna miss another
deadline that I promised
I'd make.
Well, maybe the stakes
are a little bit higher
in my world, okay?
I'm not just
QA-ing calculators.
- Excuse me?
- I didn't--
Gordon, let me
ask you something.
When is the last time
you cut their toenails?
Or which one
of your daughters
is allergic to apricots?
Do you even know
their pediatrician's name?
No, you don't?
Because you don't have to.
- I make your world possible.
- Mommy, let's go home.
It's okay, it's okay.
We're just--
just take them, Gordon.
We'll talk at home.
Donna.
- Oh, my God, you can't.
- No.
You can't even
take them.
I need you
to come to Cardiff.
- Crazy back there, huh?
- Pretty sported.
- Thought they might
come to blows.
- ( chuckles )
I hope it's okay
that I set up here.
Your gal--
what's her name--
said she thought it
would be fine.
Look, why don't you
come back next week?
Our head engineer just told me
this whole thing's no big deal,
but even so,
it's kind of distracting.
Let me level
with you, Joe.
I was never
gonna write a word
about this company.
I think its odds
of being a player
in the PC market
are about on par
with the guys who fix
my washer-dryer.
I came only
as a favor to Matt.
But lo and behold,
the universe paid me back,
gave me a story
about a company flying
too close to the sun
that burnt to a crisp
in IBM's shadow.
The pain, the dashed
hopes and dreams.
5,000 words on that,
a byline,
I might finally
get off this crappy beat
and make it back
to Wall Street
or Silicon Valley,
where the real action is.
All of which is to say
I'm not leaving
till I get this
in all its gory glory.
Maybe you don't
understand.
I'm not
asking you, Ron.
Oh, a threat.
Okay.
Let me lob one
back at you.
If I leave, if I go,
I write what I got,
and we both know
that ain't pretty.
Other hand, let me stay,
maybe I get the full story--
good with the bad.
Cardiff's engineers
are the best in the
Silicon Prairie...
- That's not saying much.
- ...and they will find
a way through this.
It's a bump,
that's all.
Great, then I'm sure
you'll want me around
to see that.
Or, wait, was that
all bullshit?
This is your
data retrieval expert?
Hello to you, too.
She did her thesis
on magnetic storage.
How long ago, Gordon?
We need current technical
know-how here.
Oh, excuse me. Like you'd
know technical know-how
if it hit you in the head.
Look, you can't be here.
- Great, that's just great.
- Come on, girls.
- Ladies, come on.
- You blow my whole day and
he tells me I have to leave?
Hold up.
Look, girls, calm down.
Get out your coloring book.
What are you
talking about?
With him here?
Come on.
Everything we do
will be open to scrutiny.
Donna:
Who, the reporter?
So tell him to leave.
It's a little
more complicated.
With you,
that's a big surprise.
I'm actually
thinking about you.
If it comes out
that you're working here,
even as a favor,
you think your bosses at TI
would be okay with it?
Is that it,
Joe, really?
Or do you not want anyone
thinking you couldn't
save your own...
( whispers )
...ass?
I don't want your wife
at the office.
What the hell's
the matter with you?
Without Donna,
this thing stays
dead on the table, Joe.
She is our best option.
Right now, she is our
only option.
Fine, but if Kane wants to know,
she's a Cardiff employee,
and don't use
your real name.
Hey, uh, I need to ask you
a couple questions.
Besides the floppy
you left in the A-drive
and the stack
near the speakers,
are you sure you never
backed up elsewhere?
( faintly )
Uh-huh.
That's a no?
Okay, how about a list of files?
Do you keep anything like that?
No. When you're in the flow
creating something,
you don't just stop
for some mindless bookkeeping.
Right, which is why
we're here right now.
( scoffs )
Who are you, anyways?
Just somebody's mother?
Do you have any clue
what it's like to work
close to the metal?
Like, any idea
what I've lost?
Well, FYI, I am
also an engineer with
a degree from Berkeley
who's not only created
my share of code,
- but given birth
to two real humans.
- Oh, God.
So yeah, I am
somebody's mother
and you could use one
right now because,
frankly, you're a mess.
Leave me alone.
Go burn a bra or something.
That's great. Sally Ride
just went to space
and here's you screwing up
at work and lashing out
like a child
at the people
trying to help you.
You slept with
the boss to get here.
Now I know why you had to.
Oh, I'm still
sleeping with him,
in case you're
wondering, bitch.
Oh, wow.
You really don't think
much of yourself, do you?
Go to hell.
( panting )
Donna:
It's melted, fine,
so it can't spin.
The read head's
damaged anyway.
We'll have to remount it
on a different spindle.
Wait, won't that just
ruin the head on that one?
Yeah, you gonna
spin it by hand?
- A micron at a time?
- Yes.
If the guys at NASA
can grind parabolic mirrors
to within one sixth
of the wavelength of yellow
light by hand,
I'm pretty sure I can control
the rotation of a disk.
In fact, my chances of success
are greater by a factor of 144.
Maybe, but no way
the ins and outs.
Exactly, which is why
we'll modify it.
Use the stepper motor
on the head, not
the spinner motor.
Remove the data
one click at a time,
back up to a third drive.
Only problem being
we'll die of old age
before you finish.
Not if the FAT's
intact.
That way, aside from
the fried files,
I can reassemble
the BIOS by deduction.
( scoffs )
I think she's
smarter than you are.
I knew that
the moment I met her.
How I'd never
really deserve her.
And, frankly, I'm amazed
she puts up with me.
( whispers )
Someone's in the doghouse.
Come on,
let's do this.
Joe:
Hey, you all right?
I brought you
something to eat.
Just go.
( keys clicking )
Okay, you can
do the transfer.
ETA on that, Ed?
Not too long.
It's coming.
Wiring's a bit tricky.
Spinner wires
are in the middle
of the ribbon.
- Mommy? I wanna go.
- I'm starving.
- Maylene...
- I'm sorry, I got rascals
of my own at home.
- What about Debbie?
- Joe sent her home.
I gotta go.
( sighs )
Fine.
Okay, I've got
nuts and raisins.
- That's what's for dinner?
- Just eat it, okay?
- Kids in Africa are
starving right now.
- Gordon...
Com on, we need
to get this done.
Hey, I can take them
if you guys wanna
keep working.
No, no, no.
We're good, thanks.
We don't need
any more of your help.
Well, where
will you be?
Uh, the garage, I guess,
just outside the fire door.
Fine, all right?
Just be careful.
There's a phone down there.
Call if you got a problem.
Okay, and we'll be right
in this room, all right?
Here, dinner,
which they will eat
and not gripe about.
I'm sure they'll be
little angels.
The good news is
I'll go blind
before I die.
Then at least
I'll have to stop.
Well, the guys
are bringing you down
another monitor.
- There.
- ( sighs )
There it is, the FAT.
It's mostly intact.
- Thank God.
- Easy, now.
It's a process.
You know, watching you work,
you know what it reminds me of?
How often you distract me
when I'm trying to work?
That night in CS-50,
remember?
When everybody
had left the lab
and you forced
yourself on me
on the motherboard
assembly table.
I recall it
a little differently.
It took five days
to rebuild the ones
that broke
- when you
swept them to the floor.
- You swept them to the floor.
Hey, romantic urgency.
Yeah, I remember.
Donna, I'm-- I'm sorry.
Okay, now leave me alone.
I gotta work.
- Okay.
- ( chair rumbles )
Okay, oh, do you want
tickle spray?
Sure.
Some guy who doesn't
work here anymore
left it in his desk,
so I stole it.
Some people think it's yucky,
but let's just try it.
Okay, ready?
( laughs )
No?
I think real
tickles are better,
what do you think?
- Right? Real tickles are good.
- ( laughing )
- You're not trash.
- Yeah, you're fun.
What?
Did someone say I was?
It's okay, girls.
You can tell me.
Well, Dad said to Mom
that you were
just like white trash.
Haley:
Yeah, they were joking.
How do you know
they were joking?
'Cause
they were laughing.
Let's go play,
Cameron.
You guys wanna see
something fun?
( gasps )
Huh?
Okay, go. Playtime's over.
Go play with your parents.
Joanie:
Let's go.
( door opens,
closes )
( garage door rattling )
( rattling stops )
I thought Joe
told you to leave.
Oh, he did.
But then we came
to an understanding.
How's the BIOS
recovery looking?
Yeah, your engineers
didn't want to talk
to me either.
They're
a prickly bunch.
I thought they were gonna
try and crucify me
the moment I set foot
down there.
Now you know
they're smart.
Must be especially
rough on you.
I mean,
22 years here--
selling diodes
and ham radios...
to mainframe software,
to this?
( chuckles )
You feeling
any guilt
letting some
IBM slickster
come in and hijack it
all away from you?
( scoffs )
First, check your facts.
No one hijacked
anything from me.
And, second, you think
your little story here
about our failed
hopes and dreams,
that gonna revolutionize
news reportin'?
Hell, just another
wad of paper
I'll wrap my dead
fish heads in.
But you
go ahead and write
your Titanic story,
the one
where we go down.
But I tell ya,
y'all should be careful.
Because when we
build this PC,
everybody
gonna wanna be in
and you...
are gonna be
outside standing there,
your little pecker
wagging in the wind.
Now, you get out of my office
before I punch you in the face.
I think
we got it.
( spray can rattling )
- ( loud crashing )
- Man: Damn it!
( gun cocks )
Brian: Ah.
( laughs )
Oh, man.
They fired you, too?
God, it's like a frickin'
horror movie over there.
Hey, oh, don't worry.
I only shoot bad guys.
Yeah.
( laughs )
Oh, oh, you're here
for payback, huh?
Justice!
What are you gonna write?
The usual, huh?
Okay, go ahead.
Do it.
I mean, they're both
such hypocrites, right?
Nose-in-the-air Donna
with her whole
careerwoman act,
and Gordon, the artiste?
Oh, please.
Like he and Joe
what's-his-face
are ever gonna create
a PC to rival the big boys.
Do it.
I swear to God,
I won't tell.
( clicks key )
( sighs )
We got it.
Kane:
Nice save.
Crisis averted, huh?
Well, we're just lucky
the file allocation table
wasn't lost.
Once I found that,
I was able to write a program
to help reassemble
the data sectors.
She's not
completely recovered,
but by my calculations,
about 93%.
- And you are?
- This is, um,
Susan Fairchild.
She's one
of our debuggers.
Thanks, Susan.
Nice work.
Hey, guys.
How about showing Ron here
how you cracked the problem?
You really got in
deep there, right?
Okay, well,
the magnetic platter
melted, right?
And it couldn't be spun.
So we remounted it.
- Kane: And you are...?
- Oh, Gordon Clark,
head engineer.
No, no, but, come on.
IBM decimated your
mainframe business.
You laid off
scores of employees.
Have you got
the resources, the guts,
to fight
in the PC world?
Joe:
Ron, three things--
nimbleness, vision,
and a complete lack of fear.
IBM's formidable,
but it's gotten fat.
( sighs )
The storage room
has no carpeting.
It's concrete.
I don't know about you,
but I'd use a mop,
not a vacuum cleaner.
I had the janitor let go,
but if you want, I can call--
My God,
you are tenacious.
They were degaussed,
all right.
But one of them had
a spreadsheet on it.
Another, part of a game.
Cameron's sloppy,
but she's not that sloppy.
She would've used
clean disks to back up on,
not those.
You engineered this.
You got her
out of the room somehow,
you made
the power surge happen,
but you grabbed a bunch
of random disks, didn't you,
and demagnetized them all
before swapping them
for Cameron's?
Congrats, you got me.
And if I hadn't
recovered the BIOS?
I would've saved
the day myself before
Kane left the building.
All of this
for a little publicity?
Don't underestimate it.
He came in here today
with zero interest
in what we were doing.
Now, whether he writes
that we're geniuses
on the cusp of something great
or misfits who almost
crashed and burned,
at least
he'll write something,
and right now
that's all we need.
And Cameron,
who's sleeping with you?
- She's just
collateral damage?
- She'll get over it.
- Plus, she's learned
to be more careful.
- ( Donna scoffs )
Look, you can think
what you want about me, Donna.
But this is their dream, too,
not just mine.
I'd hate to see
their trust in me broken
over something so minor,
so beneficial as this.
If you're smart,
and clearly you are...
you won't tell anyone.
Not even Gordon.
The kids are fine.
Thanks for asking.
Hey, would you
get them settled, please?
- What?
- Just-- I'll be there
in a minute.
Okay.
Hey.
You scared my girls.
I had to leave,
I'm sorry.
You should be.
I don't know if you heard,
but I recovered your code.
Not all of it,
but 93.6%.
Thank you.
God, what I said
to you--
No, forget it.
You were a wreck.
Makes sense
you would be.
One time when I was in school,
I spilled a whole Coke
on my motherboard.
Hadn't backed up
for weeks.
I felt like jumping off
the Bay Bridge.
But I have to tell you,
my code...
was never like yours.
Yours is, uh...
well, it's like
a piece of music.
You should go home.
Sleep, maybe eat
a real meal.
You can work
tomorrow.
No, I gotta get back
that 6.4%.
Suit yourself.
Oh, are these--
are these yours?
Oh.
Gordon.
( siren wailing )
( car door closes )
( sighs )
Was a little
fast, huh?
License
and registration?
Yeah.
Whoa, whoa, what
are you reaching for?
Just getting my license
out of the-- whoa, whoa.
What are you doing?
All right, all right.
Oh, shit.
He hit me.
No, I-- what?
Ow!
( thumping )
( door closes )
They're gonna be
a mess tomorrow.
You mean
in two hours?
( scoffs )
Man, what a day.
You were amazing.
I mean, amazing.
Susan Fairchild?
You give me my mother's
maiden name?
It was the first thing
I thought of.
So you think of me
as my mother?
No, of course not.
You're being crabby.
Come on, we both
need to get to bed.
What?
Joe fried
Cameron's hard drive
and made it look like
she degaussed her backups.
He did it on purpose
to try and get that reporter
to write about you guys,
about your PC,
about the company.
The BIOS was never lost.
He had the real backups
the whole time.
- What?
- This is the man we've
hitched our wagon to, Gordon.
This is your partner
in this whole thing.
But how could he?
I mean--
Jesus.
I mean, what he
put us all through.
Wasting my whole day
on some massive fake drama?
He only told me when I
confronted him about it.
God.
Well, did it work?
Is the reporter
gonna write the story
about us and our PC?
What?
I'm just asking.
- ( phones ringing )
- ( chatter )
John:
Jeff, we still
fishin' on Sunday?
Hey, Hank.
Saw that boy of yours
on the mound.
- ( laughs )
- God, he is bringing some
Nolan Ryan heat, that kid.
Yep, they do
grow up quick, Boz.
( groans )
( exhales )
You wanted to see me?
Because I'm doing it right now.
No, no, it's not
about that report.
It's about this one.
Not only was it late,
it was full of errors.
I looked like an idiot
in front of Mark.
Um...
I'm sorry.
What's wrong?
You're better
than this.
Now, I'm a friend.
You know that.
But I can't keep
covering for you.
I've got my own job
to think about.
As of now,
you're on probation.
Now, unless your work improves,
there may be action taken.
That's it.
( liquid pouring )
Jeez.
What the hell
happened to you?
I got careless,
fell.
( groans )
Had a close call
yesterday.
Yep.
If it hadn't been
for Donna,
who knows
where we'd be?
"Fear" playing
♪ Fear ♪
♪ It's cold
and it's gray ♪
♪ It's strange ♪
- ♪ Fear... ♪
- ( disk drive clicking )
♪ Fear ♪
♪ It's cold
and it's gray ♪
♪ I just can't explain ♪
♪ Fear ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ Same as yesterday ♪
♪ Fear ♪
♪ Fear. ♪