"Capsize" playing
- ♪ You move forward,
I move backwards...♪
- ( alarm blaring )
♪ And together
we make nothing at all ♪
♪ And everybody knows ♪
♪ How your garden's
growing tonight ♪
♪ What's this tender
fascination ♪
♪ And the boredom
emulation of love? ♪
♪ Stories to take home ♪
♪ We had your garden
grow up just right ♪
♪ You do it for me ♪
♪ You do it
with quickness ♪
♪ A man of the hour ♪
♪ As God is my witness ♪
♪ Me and my song... ♪
Yeah, I need a taxi to take me
to Eaton Microtech Labs.
Oh, I'm not from here.
Can you get the guy
with the French name on that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Mr. Concierge.
♪ You do it for money ♪
♪ A man of the hour ♪
♪ It aches in my belly ♪
♪ Me and my song ♪
♪ We'll do it alone... ♪
( gasps, groans )
( winces )
( gasps )
( grunts )
It's alive,
it's alive, it's alive.
I really appreciate you
coming home this morning.
Thank you.
I gotta shower and shave
and get back to the office.
I just wanted
to bring you this.
- You were quoted
several times.
- Oh, you mean...
( whispers )
"Susan Fairchild"
was quoted?
- French toast.
What's the occasion?
- Dad's birthday.
I thought that's
why you came home.
( whispers )
You got him a putter.
Well, well, well.
Look what the cat
dragged in.
Happy birthday.
He loves the putter.
Did you thank him,
sweetheart?
You should come to the
club with me today.
Play a quick nine?
Um, I gotta--
I got work I gotta do.
Good morning, girls.
Hey, no hello
for Daddy,
who you haven't seen
in almost two days?
Both:
Hi, Daddy.
Can we take this
to school?
- Is it a calculator?
- No, it's a TV.
Isn't that thing
incredible?
Yeah, now they can
watch TV all the time.
I just arranged
an exclusive deal
with Kazoku
to carry them
in our fall catalogue.
Mm.
( sighs )
Happy birthday
to me, right?
- Whoo-hoo!
- ( laughs )
Well, how will
your computer compare
to the IBM XT?
Ours has all the same
features as the XT,
plus-- plus
a few bonus extras.
- Retailer: Like what?
- John: Like what?
Like you can haul it
down to the no-tell motel
when you screw
your secretary
and you'd still get
your memos typed up.
"Like what?"
You try that
with an IBM PC,
hell, you'd
throw out your back.
Retailer #2:
Now, what about speed?
That seems to be all
our customers care about.
I heard you guys
were flirting
with the 286.
Yep.
Oh, I'm just
a carpetbagger
from New York.
They won't
listen to me.
Gentlemen, I think--
I think all the specs
are right there in those
packets that we gave you.
Y'all can read, right?
Joe:
First of all,
to clarify,
- secretary isn't
included at that price.
- ( retailers laughing )
As for the specs,
we were experimenting
with the 286,
but in the end,
it would only cost your
customers an arm and a leg,
so we're going with
an eight megahertz 8086.
That's almost twice as fast
as any PC on the market,
plus we're including
a floating-point math
coprocessor
that will run circles
around any IBM PC.
Let's cut to the chase
and get to the question
you came here to
have answered.
The question your CEO
will ask you at your
post-COMDEX powwow.
"What do we put
on our third shelf?"
Not the first shelf--
that's reserved for IBM.
Not even
the second shelf.
That's where
your name brand
computer goes.
The ones you have
manufactured in Taiwan
and slap
your insignia on.
The third shelf.
The "kludge" shelf.
The shelf
your stock boys detest...
because the computers
are so heavy...
and the shelves
are so low.
That's the shelf
we're talking about.
us schmucks are aiming
for, am I right?
Wrong.
This isn't
an IBM compatible clone.
This is
the new compatible.
IBM will have to
clone us.
Tell that to your CEO
and I promise you this
time next year,
you'll be sitting
in his chair asking,
"What do we put
on our third shelf?"
( overlapping questions )
( theme music playing )
( employees chattering )
Welcome back.
How was your trip?
- Who are all these people?
- New team of software
engineers.
This is Steve, our software
development manager.
Steve,
this is Cameron.
I told them
all about you.
You didn't tell me
she was a girl.
I knew your keen analytical
skills would sniff it out.
Hey--
Run those to Gordon.
Look, I can handle
all the software myself.
I already mapped out
the design on the plane.
Who told you
to do that?
No one.
I thought that--
Why? How do you think
a project this big works?
Throwing as many people
at the problem as Bosworth
will approve.
Wait, did you
send me to Cincinnati
so that you could hire
Steve and his little minions
behind my back?
Don't be paranoid.
I sent you to Cincinnati
'cause you needed the rest.
Writing the BIOS
almost killed you.
Have you guys
thought of a name yet?
I'm deciding between
"Alamo," "Death Star,"
and "George."
I can't believe
you guys don't like "Khan."
"Khan!"
Excuse me?
I wrote the BIOS.
I name it.
"Lovelace."
- "Lovelace."
- ( all laughing )
Not Linda Lovelace,
you pervs, Ada Lovelace.
As in the first computer
programmer ever?
Good name.
All right,
let's turn this baby on.
( tapping drumroll )
( clicks )
( faint whirring )
All:
Yeah!
- Larry: Yes!
- ( cork pops )
Champagne.
- Champagne.
- Good work.
Why is everyone celebrating?
The screen didn't even turn on.
- There is no screen.
- We're getting there.
I just promised a room
full of retailers a briefcase.
You couldn't fit
this crap in a gym bag.
You mean overpromised.
It must be nice to have a job
where you get to say words
without having
to actually do anything.
Did you ever
sell a computer
before I showed up here?
Did any of you?
Well, we should
probably turn it off.
I think it's
starting to smoke.
Then turn it off,
Stan.
What the hell
is this?
I asked you to do
a failure analysis
report.
I did.
I don't understand.
Can I see that?
It's here.
It got mixed up
with the supplemental
report I did.
Okay, thanks.
Next time, just make sure
the report I need is on top.
( sighs )
Stan:
If we get rid of fans,
we have a heat problem.
If we get rid
of the coprocessor,
we lose
floating-point speed.
That'll get weight
out of the case.
That'll give us
one, two pounds max.
Joe wants this to be
10 pounds lighter.
Yeah, I want my wife
to be 10 pounds lighter.
Life is about
compromise.
This isn't
a joke, Ed.
Everything is riding
on us getting this right.
And no one's leaving here
until we do, you got that?
Yes.
Rangers scored.
- Give me that watch.
- Ow, relax.
Would you rather be
pounding Shiners with Brian
at 3:00 in the afternoon?
'Cause that can be arranged.
I'm sorry.
What if we swapped out
the CRT for an LCD?
It's lighter and smaller.
And way over
our budget.
Not if you know
a guy.
( fizzling )
Man:
What's up?
I'm Lev.
That's Kenneth,
but everyone
calls him Yo-Yo.
( keyboard clicking )
- Are you playing games?
- Jesus, do you mind?
I assigned you
to write print drivers,
not play games.
- What, when?
- Well, didn't you
check the flowchart?
I mapped out all
the subroutine assignments
and which order to do them in.
Print drivers
are remedial.
Why aren't I working
on a compiler?
Because I already have
a team on it, number one.
Number two, I hear
you can't be trusted
to document your code,
and, number three,
I need you to document
your code.
Welcome
to the short bus.
Is that "Adventure"?
Yeah.
( chuckles )
Classic.
I could tell
by your keystrokes.
That thing's heroin.
Took out my graduate seminar
the night before our final.
We all flunked.
( fizzling )
Hey, Yo-Yo, I'm putting
this up on the mainframe,
so consider
yourself warned.
Gary: Perfect time
for you to come out.
This place empties out
for the long weekend.
You won't slow down
anyone's game.
That was a really nice
gift you got the girls,
the Kazoku watch.
I know you think
I spoil them.
No, no, you should
spoil them.
It sounds like you got
a really good relationship
with the guys over
at Kazoku Electronics.
Look, all I'm asking
for is an introduction.
I need a new LCD screen
for my computer
and Kazoku has
the best technology.
For a second there,
you had me convinced
you actually wanted
to play a round of golf
with me for my birthday.
I'm sorry, Gary.
I just--
look, I really
need this.
Last time you came
to me for help--
I won't let Donna
go through that again.
This isn't like
last time, I promise you.
- How's it different?
- It's completely different.
Joe, he's running
the project.
He's got over a decade
at IBM under his belt.
- Joe MacMillan?
- Yeah.
Donna keeps telling me
he's all hat and no cattle.
No, no, no, no.
He's the real deal.
Honest to God.
And I got a whole team
of engineers
that are busting
their asses for me.
And you know
John Bosworth.
I mean, Cardiff's
a solid company.
The Japs love me.
You know,
I make 'em a bundle.
They'll have
to meet with you.
They don't do business
without a face-to-face.
Yeah, I'll clear
my schedule.
Thank you.
Sorry.
And these are
the directions
to Big Star Ball
in case you
decide to come.
We had a ball
last year.
Are you forgetting?
I'm from New York.
I'm trying.
- Do you want me
to call your father?
- What?
Your father.
You just missed him.
He has a layover
this Thursday in Dallas
on his way to Hong Kong.
- ( intercom clicks )
- Did he say where
he's staying?
Debbie:
The Kerrington Hotel.
Call him
and tell him I'll meet him
at the lobby bar at 1:00.
( switch clicks )
What are you doing,
arranging a vendor
meeting without me?
They were headed back
to Tokyo in the morning.
It was now or never.
- Never. Cancel it.
- What? No.
I don't have time
to explain this to you.
- Just cancel it.
- You keep asking me
for the moon
and I finally get it for you
and now you're saying no.
How is Kazoku's
screen the moon?
They've developed
cutting-edge
LCD technology.
You want our computer
to be under 12 pounds
and slim as a briefcase?
This is how we do it.
They'll gouge us.
I have a connection.
He can get 'em down on price.
How do you
have a connection?
It's a small industry.
You meet people.
Look, I'm meeting them
at Sushi on McKinney
at 7:00.
Are you in
or are you out?
IBM doesn't even make them
with LCD screens.
Change the reservation
to Woodson's.
Japanese don't come
to Dallas to have
a shrimp cocktail
dressed up
like a sushi roll.
They come for steak.
Good call.
Hey...
nice work.
- What?
- ( chuckles )
Your comments.
They're funny.
You be careful.
I might ask you
to document all my code.
- Check this out...
- ( key clicks )
Oh, no, the printer
only prints text.
Wait, you added
a graphics mode?
And auto grayscale
conversion?
( whirring )
Oh! Cool.
Uh, Friday, a bunch of us
are going to that KCYD
car thing,
then to dinner
if you're interested.
Yeah, maybe.
Steve:
Now, how are we
doing over here?
I'm finished.
Did you check off
your module on the flowchart?
No, just told you
I'm finished.
Well, I still need you
to put a check by your name.
It's part
of the protocol.
Learned it
at Stanford B-School.
Mm, does the B
stand for bullshit?
If you have a problem,
you can come by my office
and we can discuss it
like adults.
No need to get
your panties in a wad.
Oh, I'm not
wearing any panties.
But you can stick that
in your flowchart.
You have to get rid
of that tool.
- Which one?
- I'm not kidding.
He's a terrible manager.
He can't see
the forest for the trees.
You have to get rid of him.
I don't have to do anything.
Learn to work with people.
He's assigning drivers
to the fastest coders
and compilers
to the lunkheads.
It's inefficient.
Cut him some slack.
He's under a lot of pressure.
What-- I could
handle the pressure.
Why is that so crazy?
Let's see-- you're not
exactly a people person.
You have no management
experience or any job
experience, really.
- You dropped out of college...
- Because you begged me,
asshole.
...and you lack
professionalism.
A manager doesn't
swear at his superior,
certainly not with
his office door open.
Is that
more professional?
Look, if I've given you
the impression
that because of this thing
we've got going on
that you're entitled
to special treatment,
I'm sorry.
Cameron, what
are you doing?
I'm just taking
this little thing we've
got going off the table.
Maybe that'll
wake you up.
- Uh, I left some stuff
at your apartment, so...
- ( keys clatter )
you can tell Steve
I'll report for duty
tomorrow.
I read that they don't
expect Westerners to bow,
but you're supposed
to receive their business
cards with both hands.
It's a sign of respect.
I've been to Tokyo
nine times.
Gordon Clark.
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
Guest:
The pleasure is ours.
- Hirohiko Taketa.
- Thank you.
Hirohiko Taketa.
"Hirohiko Taketa, head
of International Sales,
Kazoku Electronics."
Mr. Taketa,
thank you for being
our guest tonight.
We would do anything
for the son-in-law
of Gary Emerson.
( stammers )
I-I-I'm Gary's
son-in-law.
Oh, hai.
( chuckles )
( door closes )
Oh, sorry.
Hope I didn't scare you.
I'm Joe MacMillan.
I know
Joe MacMillan.
Senior.
He's my son.
Do you know when Joe
will be back?
Uh, no, he's--
how did you get in here?
I showed the super
my license.
You say something
with the right authority,
you generally
get what you want.
Huh, that's fascinating.
I'm just here
to get my stuff.
I bought this bat
for him.
Spent hours teaching him
how to swing correctly.
He wasn't exactly
a natural.
Didn't know Joe
had a girlfriend.
I'm not
his girlfriend.
Well, Joe's not exactly
the girlfriend type.
So, what did he do
to make you so mad at him?
What did he do
to make you so mad
at him?
Is that
what he told you?
No, he never
talks about you.
But if you had to lie
to the super to get
into his apartment,
I'm guessing
you're not exactly chummy.
Touché.
Actually, he stood me up
this afternoon.
Maybe we could
commiserate over a drink.
Thanks, but I've
got to get going.
Someone waiting
for you?
Yeah.
Well, it was nice
to meet you, Miss--
you know, I never
caught your name.
Cameron.
Not Cameron Howe?
How do you
know my name?
When my guys
came back to New York,
they couldn't stop talking
about this prodigy
named Cameron Howe.
- Right.
- Oh, yes.
They said you're
the modern Ada Lovelace.
Tomorrow, I'm taking
a 20-hour flight to Hong Kong
with Bill Gates and he's
gonna talk circles around me
and I could use
some liquid courage.
I hate to drink alone.
Don't mind me,
I'm just gonna check
the weather report
on the local news.
( all chuckle )
No, but it's-- it's really
an amazing work of engineering.
The one question I have
is how do you scale this
to a bigger size
without the display blurring?
Oh, we make
the voltage higher.
Five volts
usually enough, yeah.
But if you zap a pixel
with a voltage that high,
the adjacent pixels twist, too.
Don't you get ghosting?
What if you laid
in a third layer
of microcapacitors?
Aren't you experimenting
with that technology already?
Sony is.
It would
cost you more.
- Well, maybe--
- We can't drive up the price
till we're no
longer competitive.
Here's our offer.
You take a lower margin
on the individual screens,
we'll give you a percentage
of our profits on the back end.
It's the best I can do,
and, frankly,
I don't think you'll get
a better deal from another
PC manufacturer.
( sighs )
- Kanpai.
- All: Kanpai.
- ( coughs )
- Easy.
Lev: Is anyone else stuck
in the maze of twisty
little passages?
Yo-Yo:
Try dropping an item.
( keyboards clicking )
What?
A pirate just pounced on me
and stole my treasure.
No, no, no,
no, you shut up!
You have bad grammar.
( clicking continues )
You, come with me.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
Any of you.
All of you.
Get your asses
in here, come on.
Come on.
Come here,
get in.
How the hell do I get out
of this godforsaken cave?
( all laugh )
Really looking forward
to working with you.
Hai.
And the sales guys,
they don't get what we do.
You know, the artistry
that's involved.
All they care
about's profit.
Take my father-in-law.
Have you ever even looked
through the "Razor's Edge"?
I mean, you wouldn't believe
the schlock that guy sells.
Schlock, you know,
like stupid stuff.
Hai.
( flushing )
Schlock.
I noticed an Air Force pin
on your backpack.
- Your father's?
- Yeah.
Vietnam?
Helicopter
crew chief.
Tough job.
I was a naval officer
in the Pacific.
If anyone had told me
one day I'd be flying
to Tokyo every month
and bowing to them...
( chuckles )
So, when did you
start working for IBM?
Oh, they recruited me in 1945
to work on the Mark I.
- With Grace Hopper?
Did you meet her?
- Oh, sure.
- Did it really
weigh four tons?
- Five.
We used it in the Navy to
calculate artillery firing.
I knew right then
I wanted to work for
Big Blue when I got out.
Best company
in the world.
And I still
don't understand what
possessed Joe to leave.
I was surprised
you turned us down.
You could've been
the next Grace Hopper.
Instead, you're in line
to be another programmer
no one remembers.
( chuckles )
Oh, my God, you're right.
Yeah, instead of writing
software for a brand-new
machine,
I could've been
getting coffee for the guy
who warms the seat
for the guy who writes
the software.
What was I thinking?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
That was out of line.
You're not the one
I'm angry at.
It's a tricky thing,
fathers and sons.
Your dad's lucky
to have a daughter.
I bet you'd never
stand him up if he
came to see you.
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
He didn't make it
back, did he?
You couldn't have been
more than 10 years old
at the time.
I-- excuse me.
Joe:
They picked up the check.
Are you too drunk
to comprehend that means
they're done with us?
I should never
have let you come.
Let me come?
I arranged this deal.
No, Gary did,
and then you insulted him.
Nothing says,
"Don't trust us"
quite like bad-mouthing
your own father-in-law.
Look, your father works
at IBM and you shit on them
all the time to everyone.
Not to the Japanese.
Look, you may be good
with a soldering iron,
but when it comes
to business,
the big picture,
you have no idea.
Hey, hey.
I'm not the one screwing
"Cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs."
- Leave her out of this.
- Like that's not gonna
blow up in our face!
Go back to your workstation
with the rest of the grunts.
I'll fix this
in the morning.
With what, Joe,
your words?
Donna was right.
You're all hat
and no cattle.
Why don't you build
a computer with Donna?
Oh, wait,
you tried that.
( engine starts )
( tires squealing )
( engine roars )
Gordon on phone:
Your dad's gonna kill me.
Well, I bet it wasn't
as bad as you think.
Look, I'm telling you,
it was.
I really screwed
the pooch this time.
Well, I'm sure
it'll work out somehow.
- ( rings )
- Oh, honey, I've got
pies in the oven.
- We can talk more about this
when you get home.
- Okay.
Okay, yeah, I'll--
( phone rings )
What, Gordon?
Uh, it's Hunt.
Am I catching you
at a bad time?
No, no, no.
It's wonderful.
I mean...
what's up?
Well, the reason I'm calling
is 'cause I had a chance
to go over that
other report of yours,
and I wanna say
I was really impressed.
I love that you took
the initiative.
Well, thank you.
Listen...
I wanted to apologize
for snapping at you
the other day.
I was getting hammered
from upstairs and,
what can I say?
I shouldn't have
taken it out on you.
Oh, it's
no big deal, really.
I just yelled at my kids
when I got home.
Well, that's what
they're there for.
( Hunt chuckles )
Well, I don't want to
cut into your evening
any more than I already have.
Oh, no, I'm just
making some peach pies
for my parents'
barbecue.
Peach pies?
I love peach pie.
( Hunt chuckles )
Do you put vodka
in your dough?
Vodka?
My granny, she used
to substitute half the water
for a shot of vodka.
She said it kept the crust
from getting all soggy
from the fruit filling.
I think she did it
so if her pie didn't turn out,
everyone would be
too drunk to notice.
Oh, well, she sounds
like a smart lady.
Yeah, she was
the best.
Well, I...
better let you
get back to bakin'.
If you have any left over,
feel free to save me a slice.
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good night, Donna.
Can he call you in the morning?
Now's not a really good time.
- It's kinda urgent.
- ( faint chatter )
Sweetheart, can you
come to the door
for a second?
We're hosting
game night.
Fun.
( quietly )
He's drunk.
What happened?
( stammers )
Are you okay?
Sorry, I don't usually...
No, it's perfectly
all right.
I think you're under
a lot of stress at work.
Joe's all wrong
about you.
( chuckles )
Joe's wrong about
a lot of things.
How close is he
to giving up on
all this?
I don't know.
He's pretty determined.
He just hired
a whole team
of programmers
and a manager
behind my back.
Really
pissed me off.
I hate to say it,
but that sounds
like Joe.
Did he pull this
at IBM?
All the time.
You know how he got
his three promotions
at IBM?
He took them.
One time,
he actually lied
to a supervisor--
guy who'd been with us
for over 20 years--
warned him that he
was going to be let go
and then strongly
suggested that he
tender his resignation
to maintain his dignity.
Poor guy believed him.
Hmm.
Well, if you say something
with the right authority,
you generally
get what you want.
You're so
full of shit.
What, did you actually
think I was gonna roll over
and just tell Joe
what a great guy you were?
You're both disgusting.
I don't think you
understand who you've
gotten into bed with.
It's only a matter of time
until he blows everything up.
He always does.
- Well, you would know.
- I gave him the world...
and he spat
in my face.
He thinks everything
belongs to him...
you included.
( card taps )
For when
you figure that out.
( crickets chirping )
( tapping keyboard )
( playing
"Fantaisie-Impromptu" )
( car approaches )
( car door opens,
closes )
( music continues )
I'll only be
a minute.
We made a mistake
last night.
We offended you,
and for that,
I am sorry.
Mr. Clark
was too ashamed to come,
so I promised I would
apologize on his behalf
for getting drunk,
for giving the impression
that he doesn't respect
his father-in-law,
the man who was
gracious enough to put us
into contact with you.
That is not the case.
Not for him,
and certainly
not for me.
I'm not exaggerating
when I say
that I wouldn't be where
I am today if it weren't
for my father.
The day I graduated
from his alma mater,
he brought me
into his company, IBM.
He taught me the ropes.
He taught me everything
I know.
He told me to swing
for the fences and I've
never stopped swinging.
I know it's a risk
showing up like this,
but I will do
anything
to make you reconsider
being in business with us.
Excellent.
Bellboy:
Sir?
You forgot
your magazine.
I'm done with that.
Cameron:
Oh, don't bother.
- You're fired.
- Excuse you?
Oh, and it's not
'cause you're a tool,
which you are.
You can't fire me.
I'm your boss.
Hey.
Do you want
all your software
programmed in 11 weeks
for half of what
you're spending?
Is this
a trick question?
Brooks' Law,
"The Mythical
Man-Month."
The one useful book
I read in college.
Brooks said that
adding programmers
to speed up
a software project
only makes it later.
She's got
a real attitude problem.
Oh, also, I'm taking
over Steve's job.
- See what I mean?
- How would you know
which programmers to keep?
Do you even
know their names?
Hey!
( whistles )
Coder monkeys,
come here.
How many of you
got sucked into "Adventure"
last night?
I knew it.
She's sabotaging
the project, Joe.
Okay, just curious--
how many of you figured out
what order to push
the buttons in at the dam?
And how many of you
got out of the cave
by breaking the code?
I had to get home
to feed my cat.
Cameron:
Which back doors
did you use?
- Programmer: "Xyzzy."
- "Plover."
- "Plugh."
- Okay.
Lev, Yo-Yo, the rest
of you guys who cheated,
you get to keep
your jobs.
Those of you who played
fair and square,
thank you very much,
but you can go home.
Explain.
To play an honest game,
you have to be good
at solving puzzles.
But to cheat, you have
to be great at solving code.
Those are the guys
I need on my team--
the ones who can
break into the code,
find the back doors,
figure out "Plover"
and "Xyzzy"
and "Fee Fie Foe Foo"
to get it done.
- Did you find
"Fee Fie Foe Foo"?
- No.
Steve, I'll write you
a nice letter
of recommendation.
( tapping )
When I first heard
I'd be working
for Gordon Clark,
I wasn't sure
he even knew his way
around a motherboard.
Well, I've been proven wrong
a hundred times over,
and, today, my respect
for this guy has been
taken to a whole new level.
To Gordo,
for kicking ass
and taking names.
All:
To Gordo.
Thanks, Gordon.
Good job, buddy.
Hey, I see you told them
the good news about
the LCD screen.
Yeah, everyone's excited.
Good, I thought maybe
you didn't get my message.
No, I did.
Figured you'd
come by my office.
I've got work to do.
Don't you think
you owe me a thank-you?
No, Joe.
Actually, I don't.
Joe:
Right.
I only saved
your ass, the deal,
and your relationship
with your father-in-law.
( chuckles )
Gordon tell you how
he almost tanked the deal?
Joe, don't.
First, he does
eight shots of whiskey
trying to keep up with
the Japanese-- huge mistake.
So now he's wasted
and he follows the
chief engineer into--
Joe, I hate
to bust your bubble,
but you didn't save
a damn thing.
Gary did after
I went to his house
and asked him--
no, I begged him--
got down on my knees
to convince them
to reconsider.
The deal was done
before you ever got
to the hotel.
Do you want
his phone number
to thank him?
Look, you guys
take off.
I'll figure out
the heating problem.
Joe:
Cameron...
are you going
to this bowling alley
thing later?
I don't know.
It sounds dumb,
but some of the coders
are going.
It's amazing
what passes for
culture in Dallas.
I saw you took
your stuff out of
my apartment last night.
And a few things
that don't belong to you.
What things?
Don't get me wrong,
I think it's sweet
that you wanted
to read the article in the
"Wall Street Quarterly."
I didn't take it.
There's no shame
in caring about our project.
I just need it back
so I can send it to
some retailers.
Your dad came
by the apartment.
He took it.
Did you talk to him?
Uh, I didn't
stay long.
The guys
are waiting for me.
"All Night Long"
playing on P.A.
Radio DJ:
We just drove
this spanking new
1983 Datsun 280ZX
off the lot.
Now, the Japs say their cars
are stronger than ours.
We're gonna see
about that.
Step up, folks.
It's only $5 a swing.
We're gonna stay here
until that sucker is
flat as a pancake.
Come on up here,
ladies!
"Living in the USA"
playing in background
( cheering )
♪ Stand back,
what'd you say? ♪
I won't pay ♪
♪ Stand back,
I'd rather play ♪
it's my freedom ♪
♪ Yeah, don't worry
about me, babe ♪
♪ I've got to be free,
babe ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, yeah ♪
♪ Do, do, do, do,
do, do ♪
- ♪ Living in the USA... ♪
- ( cheering )
♪ Do, do, do, do,
do, do ♪
♪ Living in the USA ♪
- ♪ Stand back,
dietician... ♪
- Whoo!
♪ Stand back, politician,
mortician... ♪
( cheering continues )
♪ Living in the USA ♪
♪ Come on, baby ♪
♪ Ow ♪
♪ I see a yellow man,
a brown man ♪
♪ A white man,
a red man ♪
- ♪ Looking
for Uncle Sam... ♪
- ( cheering )
♪ To give you
a helpin' hand ♪
♪ But everybody's
kickin' sand ♪
♪ Even politicians ♪
♪ We're living
in a plastic land ♪
♪ Somebody give me
a hand, yeah ♪
♪ We're gonna
make it, baby ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ We're going
to shake it, baby... ♪
( theme music playing )