What the hell?
( grunts )
Man on TV watch:
...Alicia's arrival
is imminent,
- currently traveling west--
- ( crackles )
( groans )
( man continues )
...approaching 75 miles
per hour,
expected to exceed that,
before reaching shore sometime
late tomorrow morning.
Reports of oil company
employees
being evacuated
by helicopter
from offshore rigs
in the path of the storm
have punctuated the fear
and trepidation
that's felt by many.
Advanced computer
probability...
- ( sloshes )
- ( man on TV continues )
( Joe and Cameron moaning,
panting )
Cameron:
Hold on, wait.
Wait.
- What's wrong?
- Where did you--
how did you get these?
Really?
I was
in high school.
( moans )
I'd been saving up money
for a long time.
Summer jobs
and everything.
And I bought
a '64 Chevy Nova.
Bright yellow,
love at first sight.
The day I got it,
I took some friends out.
And it was
mid-February and cold.
I mean, bitter cold.
( Joe sighs )
Ice on the roads.
No one should've been
out that night.
Hold on.
Is this true?
What do you mean?
You're lying to me.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
The truth is--
God, this is embarrassing.
When I was a kid,
I had a buddy
who lived
out on this farm road
and there was this mill
rusted to hell.
One day I dared him.
I said, "Mike"--
Oh, my God.
Stop.
Is this another lie?
Why do you care, Cameron?
I mean, honestly.
Stop handling me.
It's just a question.
But why do you care
about the answer?
You are too
screwed up for words.
Because I don't want to tell
sad stories in bed with you?
- When did this become that?
- What's "this"?
Our routine?
You come over whenever,
I don't know, you need to,
and I'm happy to oblige.
Now all of a sudden
you're getting pissed 'cause
I don't want to play house.
Don't do that.
It's just a question.
You designed the routine.
( groans )
Well, it's no longer
doing anything for me.
This has gotten boring.
You're free to leave
whenever you like.
- You have gotten boring.
- Like I said.
- You want a piece
of advice, Joe?
- Not really.
Your whole thing,
it attracts people,
but it won't
keep them around.
Authenticity is what
inspires people.
If you want to lead people,
you have to show them
who you really are.
Otherwise, you're just
a thousand-dollar suit
with nothing inside.
No one gives a shit.
( thumps )
- What time is it?
- Shh.
Go back to sleep.
It's late.
( groans )
Mm, you smell like beer.
( moans )
I love you so much.
Gordon.
You're so beautiful.
Stop it.
I have to sleep.
I can't.
I have so much tomorrow.
I have to pick up the cake.
And I have to do it
before work 'cause
they close at 6:00.
You poor lady.
And Joanie's become fixated
on this Cabbage Patch Doll
or Kid or whatever.
She got so worked up
talking about it
she started crying...
tears of mania.
What is it?
( yawns )
It's a doll.
It's a stuffed baby.
I'll get it.
- What?
- I'm getting it.
Gordon Clark
to the rescue.
Oh, my God, really?
That would be amazing.
Don't give it
another thought.
Oh, go to sleep,
Drunky.
( sighs )
"Sooner Than Now" playing
♪ When the damage
is done ♪
♪ And we lie here,
what good am I now? ♪
♪ If you close your eyes ♪
♪ I think I might feel
sooner than now... ♪
Rain check.
Big storm's supposed
to be coming in.
Thanks.
♪ And you see it begin ♪
♪ If we lie here,
what good am I now? ♪
♪ Don't know how to win ♪
♪ Break down again
sooner than now. ♪
( door closes )
( theme music playing )
( TV playing )
( sighs )
How was your show
last night?
My amp caught on fire.
Probably the best part.
I thought you'd be there.
Where were you?
Out.
( keyboard clicking )
- What is that?
- Modified version
of "Adventure."
I made it
for you.
A stupid thing
I did for fun.
Oh, thanks.
Yo-Yo:
You going to work?
I'll give you a ride.
"A gifted man bears his gifts
into the world not for himself,
but for the people
among whom he is placed.
Because the gifts
are not his.
He himself is a gift
to his community."
Henry Ford said that.
Did pretty well for himself.
There are many gifted
men and women in this room,
and this moment,
we bring our creation
into the world.
Today, with the touch
of a button,
we start a ripple effect
that will be felt
through our community
for generations.
Thanks to our engineers,
we have a prototype.
Thanks to our
programming team,
we have an operating
system in place.
And now, finally...
we bring
our creation to life.
- Let Bosworth do it.
- Yo-Yo: Yeah, let Boz.
- Man: Boz!
- Man #2: Hey, Boz.
- Cameron: Boz!
- Nah.
Yeah.
Boz, go.
- ( crew shouting )
- Go Boz!
- Boz!
- Do it!
Yeah, all right.
( crew chanting )
Boz, Boz, Boz, Boz...
All right. Okay.
( chanting stops )
Well, ladies
and gentlemen...
a time comes when...
well, you gotta grab your balls
and jump, am I right?
( laughing )
- ( button clicks )
- ( computer whirring )
- ( beeps )
- ( crew cheering )
( voices overlapping )
Hey, congratulations.
Thank you so much.
I'll see you soon.
Not bad.
- Are we good?
- Yeah.
Sorry about
how things have been.
This process doesn't always
bring out my best.
That's true
of us both.
We should celebrate.
Come over for dinner
tomorrow night.
I don't think you've seen
more than my garage.
Yeah,
you got it.
It's done.
Miss Howe?
So, that's it.
When can we expect
the peripheral drivers
from your team?
Is this how you're
gonna talk to me
from now on?
How would you like me
to talk to you?
Like you're
flesh and blood.
I'm sorry if my tone
is businesslike,
but I am your boss
and this is,
in fact, a business.
Oh, my God.
So lifelike.
"Rich Daddy" playing
♪ You got money? ♪
♪ Well, then,
you're living the good life ♪
♪ You got a big fat daddy
at home writing checks
tonight ♪
♪ You got nothing? ♪
♪ Well, then,
you're living a bad life ♪
♪ You got a big, fine car ♪
♪ And you eye me
while you pass me by ♪
♪ A rich daddy? ♪
♪ No, I never had one ♪
♪ No, no,
I never had one ♪
♪ You got money? ♪
♪ Well, then,
you're living... ♪
( music fades )
( murmurs )
( laughs )
Gordon.
Our computer's
gonna have a personality.
An operating system
that asks you questions,
you answer it back.
You interact.
What?
Um, I need an additional
384k of RAM.
Um... no.
- ( all chuckling )
- What do you mean, no?
I mean, it's completely
out of the question.
Operating systems
are total pigs.
Even with the added memory,
you're gonna be stealing from
the other applications...
- Yeah.
- ...and slowing
the entire machine down.
I know, but, Gordon,
figure out a way around that.
- Cameron, it's done.
- No, it's--
- Look at it. It's done.
- No, it's not done.
It's-- it's--
it works fine,
but it needs a soul.
It needs to be something
that people can fall
in love with.
We can do that.
Okay, if there's one thing
that I've learned
in the 15 years
of doing this
is that at some point,
you have to stop
changing things.
You have to be happy
with what you've made.
( slaps table )
You're scared.
What would I
be scared of?
Yeah, why don't we make
the machine jerk us off, too?
( men laugh )
And I can program
hundreds of commands
in the operating system
for it to understand
accounting for regional
variance in speech,
program 10 ways for it
to respond to each.
It would be
conversational.
like speaking
to a human being.
- Slow down.
- You've played "Adventure."
It's like that, except
instead of, "I want
to cross the stream,"
you input "I want
to run WordStar."
You tell it
what you want it to do.
What are the hardware
implications?
Have you talked
to Gordon about this?
Gordon is too scared
to try anything new
or different
because he's traumatized
from being a loser
his entire life.
I think you might be
overstating that slightly.
Okay.
See this?
This I made with my dad
when I was a little kid.
It's a stupid,
stuffed thing,
but my dad wiggled its head
and he gave it a voice
and he brought it
to life.
I named it.
I fell in love with it.
This is
the sort of loyalty
we can create.
We have to get a share
of the market first.
We have to show that we can
compete with the majors
before we start
changing things up.
Maybe for a second generation,
we could do something
like this.
This is because
of last night.
I haven't given that
a second thought.
I thought you said
this was a business.
It is.
If we go with a standard
operating system,
I know what is
going to happen.
There are no surprises
down that road, no pitfalls.
We will go to COMDEX,
we will make it into Sears,
we will sell 150,000 units,
guaranteed.
You're offering me
none of that.
Gosh, you're right.
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I guess with all
your grandstanding,
I somehow
got you confused
with a visionary.
I guess it just doesn't
matter what you're saying
as long as people
are listening, right?
What the hell
does that mean?
Forgive me.
I just thought something
around here should have a soul.
( door closes )
I may need you
to walk me through this.
It's possible some of it's
going over my head.
Yeah, no problem.
Does Gordon understand
everything that comes
out of your mouth?
Yeah, as long as it's
about computers.
Hm. How's his project
coming along?
Oh, sorry.
( softly )
His super secret project.
It's going well.
It's eating up
a lot of his time.
You know, it can always
be faster, it can always
be smaller.
Mm-hmm.
They solved
the real estate
problem, though.
Did you help them
with that?
Maybe.
What was the solve?
Chips on both sides
of the board.
So simple.
I guess you're everyone's
secret weapon, huh?
Super secret.
Speaking of,
corporate's gonna
want a presentation
of this work.
I'm gonna need you
by my side.
Would you be
up for that?
A little business trip?
Of course.
Good.
Yes, good.
Cameron tell you
her bright idea about
the operating system?
It's insane,
right?
I trust that you
told her no.
Tell me you told her
it was out of the question.
I don't know.
She might be
onto something.
- It's certainly unique.
- "Unique"?
You didn't write "unique"
on the board three months ago.
- Maybe I should have.
- You wrote "faster,"
you wrote "cheaper."
Anyway, that's not the point.
Do you know how much real
estate that would take?
I'd have to rethink
the entire layout
of the board.
Greatness comes
at a price, no?
Yeah, and I've
paid that price.
Do you know how many nights
I've missed putting my kids
to bed?
You know how
many all-nighters
I've spent here?
You asked me
to do something
and I did it.
It was impossible
and I did it anyway.
It's a thought experiment.
And I'm considering it.
Well, don't.
Just don't consider it.
I'm gonna do
whatever I want to do
and you're gonna do
whatever I tell you to do
because that's the way
this relationship works.
Gordon:
And Joe tells me
he's actually considering it.
You can't change it.
It's a thing of beauty.
I don't know.
Maybe he's right.
No, Gordon, you built
a beautiful machine.
You have to
stand up for it.
Joe MacMillan's
an asshole.
He doesn't know
a fraction of what you do
about what makes
a good computer.
Daddy, is the hurricane
gonna come?
No, no, no, no.
We might get a big storm,
some rain,
but the hurricane
can't reach us here.
Houston might
get walloped, but--
Ahem.
We're safe here.
You guys go play.
Oh, hey, did you get
the you-know-what?
- What's that?
- The Cabbage...
Did I get cabbage?
No, the--
( whispers )
the Cabbage Patch Kid.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I left it at the office.
I didn't want
Joanie to find it.
She snoops, you know?
Anyway, sort of
the worst part of it is--
please keep in mind
that you love me when
I tell you this,
but before
everything went down,
I invited Joe
for dinner tomorrow.
- Dinner here?
- I know, it felt like
the right thing to do.
You know?
Smooth things over.
Well, do you think
this idea
could really compromise
what you've done?
Yeah.
Well, you have to do
whatever you can
to change his mind.
Even if that means
inviting him into our home.
It's your machine, Gordon.
Don't let him ruin it.
Yeah.
( weather reporter
speaking faintly on radio )
"Happy People" playing
♪ Happy, happy, happy,
happy people... ♪
- ( keyboard clicking )
- ♪ Smilin' in their cars,
smilin' happily ♪
♪ Man, it looks like Mars,
is that the world for me? ♪
♪ I knew a happy
little girl ♪
♪ Trapped in her happy
little world ♪
♪ Ravaged from desire ♪
♪ La la la la-la-la
la-la ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ La la la la-la-la
la-la ♪
♪ Yeah... ♪
( music continues )
( bangs )
( can snaps )
So, what's going on
in there?
Is something wrong?
I'm stuck.
( rain pattering,
thunder rumbling )
- ( knocking on door )
- Come in.
Hey, you need
a ride to work?
Uh, no, I'm on a roll.
( keyboard clicking )
What?
Hey, did you
start the tests
on those drivers?
No, I'm waiting
for the coders
to give them to me.
Hey, uh...
- Lev.
- Yeah, I know. Lev.
Listen, I was wondering
when we were gonna get
some of the drivers.
We need to start end-to-end
testing as soon as possible.
I'm working
on the OS expansion.
What? Who told you
to work on that?
Cameron did.
Did Joe
approve that?
Go back to working
on the driver, okay?
I'm the boss,
not Cameron.
Well, Cameron's
in charge of software.
Well, I'm in charge
of stopping idiotic things
from happening.
And you can trust me.
I'm not screwing
the product manager
to get my way.
What?
Lev, just go back to working
on the driver, okay?
I'll straighten
this out.
- Gordon, your wife called.
- ( groans )
She wanted me
to remind you
about the...
The Cabbage Patch.
( sighs )
Do you know
of a toy store nearby?
Well, can you
find one, Debbie?
- Yes.
- That'd be great.
( faint thunder rumbling )
No...!
- Son of a bitch.
- Hey, pal. Hey there.
You ain't looking
for a Cabbage Patch
by any chance?
- Yeah. Yeah, I am.
- I got one.
I paid 80 bucks for it
'cause these jerks marked it up
'cause it was the last one.
And now they won't
let me return it.
- I'll take it.
- Honestly?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Oh, you're a lifesaver.
- Thank you.
It's right here.
You are really
saving my butt.
Likewise,
believe me.
All right, well,
now I might go home
and beg the wife for sex.
- ( chuckles )
- Probably get some, too.
Well, good luck.
( engine starts,
tires squealing )
( thunder rumbling )
No.
No!
Hey, where are you
with that module?
- Are you kidding me?
- What?
Gordon retasked us
all with drivers.
You keep changing
directions on us.
This sucks.
Just figure out
what you want us to do
and we'll do it, Jesus.
Get all the coders
in my office.
Now.
I don't know
what anyone else
has told you,
but I'm your manager.
You take instructions
from me, okay?
- That's what
everyone else is saying.
- Well, they're wrong, okay?
I need that module
for the OS and I need it
today.
Any questions?
I got a question.
Are you banging
Joe MacMillan?
( laughing )
Oh, yeah, I'm stupid
for thinking a toy store
might carry the world's
most popular toy.
- Hello?
- ( rain pattering )
Debbie!
- Any luck?
- Not yet!
( keys beeping )
Uh, yes, I'm looking
for a Cabbage Patch Kid.
You do?
Uh, really?
C-can you
put it on hold?
No, I will come
right now.
Look, do not sell
that Cabbage Patch.
Hello?
- Gordon?
- What?
( Gordon grunts )
You were incredible
last night.
I--
I would never, okay?
Y-y-you guys
know Donna, right?
( mutters )
( doorbell rings )
( thunder rumbling )
Joe, glad you could make it
in this downpour.
Oh, come in.
Gordon's not back yet,
but he should
be here soon.
Uh, '66 Bordeaux.
Really interesting.
Thank you.
How thoughtful.
You know Joanie
and Haley, right?
Girls, say hi.
This is Joe,
Daddy's work friend.
- Girls: Hi, Joe.
- Evening.
So, how's everything
going at work?
Gordon tells me things
are progressing nicely.
Yeah, moving
right along.
- Haley: Hi.
- Hi.
( giggles )
That shoe you're sitting on
comes all the way from Italy.
Where's that?
Far away from here.
Gordon should be back
any minute.
Did I say that
already?
Man on radio:
Galveston is once again
braced for a major
hurricane tonight.
Winds exceeding
110 miles per hour...
- Where are you going?
- Home.
Oh, come on.
It's pissing rain out there.
Come have a drink with me.
- ( groans )
- Come on, I'll make you
a Cardiff Special.
I'm not taking no
for an answer.
Come on,
shake it, kid.
Hope everything's
all right.
No, everything's fine.
If I know my husband,
he's out right now
running around frantically,
( whispering )
trying to find
a Cabbage Patch Kid.
- ( girls giggling )
- Oh, hi.
Oh, girls, would you
leave him alone, please?
- How old are you?
- I'm 35, why?
I don't know.
I'm six.
Hey, okay, okay.
What about a fort?
- Okay.
- Would you like
to build a fort?
All right, uh...
Do you girls know
if we can find any blankets?
- Okay.
- Okay, let's turn
that chair around.
- Joanie: Okay.
- Whoa.
Here we go.
All right, everyone in.
- Come on, everyone in.
Everyone in.
- Yay!
( girls laughing )
So, Gordon tells me
you're thinking
of doing something
experimental with the OS?
I'm considering it.
The truth is, I just
want to do something great.
How did torturing Cameron
fit into that?
I regret that...
but it was about getting
the world's attention.
I guess I also want to do
something successful.
Well, then you should
listen to Gordon.
He's actually a genius.
Why do you think
I chose him?
You know the competition.
The only way to cut into
their market share
is by doing what they do
better or cheaper or both,
and you can do that
if you stick with what
you've got.
There's something
to be said for
ingenuity, no?
Well, sure.
Exactly.
That's what I'm saying.
There's ingenuity in there.
You've been sitting
with this machine
for a few months now.
It's easy to lose sight
of what's great
when it's
right in front of you.
You get used to it.
The computer you two built
is a work of art,
and not only that,
it'll sell.
So you can believe
in your original vision.
You made it all happen.
- ( thunder crashing )
- Whew, God Alfrighty.
Jeez, it's coming
down now.
( chuckles )
What was that dustup
in the bullpen
this afternoon?
( groans )
It's a long story.
Yeah, well,
I got nothing but time.
Clark, huh?
Gordon is good.
- Mm.
- He's really good.
- Mm-hmm.
- But Gordon wants
to build a computer
that'll impress
all the other people
who build computers.
I want to build
something for people
who never thought
they'd want a computer,
who don't know
anything about them.
I want to build
a computer for you.
Hey, now.
I know my way around
a damn computer.
I've been in this business
since before you were
in diapers, kid.
All right.
You know what I mean.
I want to build something
that makes people fall in love.
( faint thunder rumbles )
How'd you fall in love?
Computer Club.
I didn't have
a ton of friends
in junior high.
Oh, I am shocked
by that.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I was hiding out
in a classroom at lunch
and the Computer Club
came in.
I just pretended
I was there on purpose.
Mr. Monroe
taught us BASIC
and it was like
finding water
in the middle
of the desert.
For the first time,
I knew how to talk
to something.
I finally had
the right language.
- ( thunder rumbles )
- You're talking just fine now.
- I'm drunk.
- ( Bosworth chuckles )
Listen, now, the--
the theatrics
out there today.
( sighs )
Be more careful, Cam.
I'm a big girl.
I can take care of myself.
Oh, hell, I know that.
That's plain as day.
It's just...
( sighs )
Some of the people
around here,
no matter what they say,
or even what they think--
part of them wants
to see you shit the bed
on this thing.
Why's that?
'Cause you're the future.
Ain't nothing scarier
than that.
When I was little,
any time there was
a big storm,
my dad would
take us out in it
to show me
there was nothing
to be afraid of.
Then a kid in our
neighborhood got pinned
under a fallen tree
and so he stopped
doing that.
( sighs )
I feel like parenting
used to be different.
( thunder crashing )
My mom used to take me
up to the roof
of our old Victorian
to look at the stars.
That any of us survived
is a miracle.
- ( loud thunderclap )
- ( screaming )
Hey, hey, it's okay.
You afraid
of the hurricane?
But you've got
hurricane zappers
right here.
You don't know
about hurricane zappers?
Oh, yeah, these.
Just point them
at the storm and it
can't hurt you.
- ( flashlights click )
- Here, I'm telling you
the truth.
- Give it a shot.
- Joanie: It'll work
through the roof?
Oh, yeah.
A bigger storm, you might
need to go outside.
But a little storm
like this, through
the roof should be fine.
- Haley: Let's try it.
- There they go.
( thunder crashing )
( bell jingles )
( crashes )
( loud buzzing )
( thunder continues )
( buzzing, crackling )
( buzzing )
( fizzing, popping )
( buzzing, popping )
( thunder crackles )
( laughing )
It's not working.
Mind if I give it
a shot?
It's a big storm.
You have to do it outside.
- No, sweetheart--
- You're probably right.
You're probably right.
- Joe, you don't have to--
- Okay, follow me.
You really
don't have to.
- Be careful, don't
let her get hurt.
- Her?
- Anastasia.
- You named it.
Mine is Sharky.
And they're
your friends?
Huh.
I promise to be
very careful.
Okay, watch.
- Joanie: What's he doing?
- Haley: Let's go see.
( thunder crashing )
Whoa!
( giggling )
It works
a lot better outside.
( thunder crashing )
( thunder rumbling )
- ( giggling )
- All right, all right.
- Here you go.
- Oh, thanks.
- Gordon!
- Girls: Daddy!
We were
worried about you.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm so sorry I'm so late.
What happened to you?
Oh, thanks for sticking around,
Joe. I appreciate it.
It's no problem.
Should we eat?
Did you guys eat?
I should go,
leave you guys alone.
Storm's clearing up
anyway.
Well...
Joe, I need
to talk to you.
Oh, no, Gordon,
you can talk tomorrow.
Hey, thanks for inviting me.
Uh, I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bye, girls.
- Girls: Bye.
( thunder rumbles )
Hey, are you
okay?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
( rain pattering )
( rapping )
What do you want?
Do you have
anybody?
What are you
talking about?
If you got stuck
in a hurricane,
do you have anybody
you would call?
I don't.
Show me what
you've been working on.
Press "Enter."
( key clicks )
Don't be rude.
Computer's talking to you.
Answer it.
- ( laughs )
- You messing with me?
Well, it only does
first names right now.
( rainfall continues )
When I was a kid,
my mom used to take me
up to the roof
to look at the stars.
She was wild and...
experimented
with drugs.
One time, she let go
of my hand
and I fell
three stories
and landed on a fence
in the front yard.
I spent most of
the next two years
in a hospital bed.
Cameron?
Yeah?
This is
really good.
(Music playing )