( rain pattering )
( thunder crashing )
( faint buzzing )
Haley:
Daddy?
Gordon, are you okay?
You're screaming.
- What?
- You're screaming
at the top of your lungs.
- Joanie: Mommy!
- What time is it?
Why aren't you in bed?
This analysis report-- I have
to leave for Lubbock Tuesday
and it has to be perfect.
- Did I wake up the kids?
- You probably woke
the neighborhood.
- Are you sure
you're okay?
- Yeah.
Monkeys, it's okay.
I'm coming.
( girls crying )
Can I get you some dinner
before I take off?
Can you still
call it dinner at
2:30 in the morning?
I'm good, Debbie.
Thanks.
"Can I get you some dinner
before I take off?"
- Oh, be nice.
- She's right.
You gotta eat.
Look who's talking.
All work and no play
makes Joe a dull boy.
Hmm?
- There's got
to be another way.
- We've tried everything.
- Well, get more creative.
- I can't.
I move more things around,
it's going to start
to look bad.
It'll be
a problem.
Personal computer division
is already operating
at a massive deficit.
By close of business
next week,
the hole will be so deep,
it will take the entire
company with it.
You keep this
between us.
Do you understand?
( Cameron chuckling )
( chuckling,
chattering )
We shouldn't be
eating in here.
- ( computer keys clicking )
- I know.
I just like
looking at it.
It kinda
turns me on.
Oh, is that weird?
Joe, that's
a live current.
( pops )
It's only a few volts.
( gasps, pants )
- What are you doing?
- ( clicking )
( shudders )
I'm turning you on.
( current humming )
- ( grunts )
- ( gasps )
( laughs )
( phone ringing )
No, someone's
calling.
It's 3:00
in the morning.
( ringing continues )
No, no, I'm thrilled
you'll do it,
I'm just surprised
you called back.
I left you
a few messages, but that
was several weeks ago.
Oh, next week?
I had no idea he was
showing his photos here.
I'd love to see that.
I would love to see you,
work with you on this.
Oh, the sixth.
I'll look forward to that.
( chuckles )
How have you been?
( theme music playing )
Can't say I'm exactly happy
about the extra memory
- or Cameron's expanded O/S...
- The lasagna is in the freezer.
Don't forget to take it out
and let it thaw before
you reheat it in the oven.
You know, that's the past.
We have to move on.
...in case you need it
the number for the hotel
is on the fridge.
- Gordon, did you hear me?
- I know what people
are saying.
They're saying
that I roll over
for software.
- But the truth is--
- Gordon, look at me.
Lasagna, freezer,
thaw, oven,
number on the fridge.
Got it.
Look, the QA tests,
they're gonna go fine.
There's gonna be
disappointment,
but we need to focus
on the net gain here.
- They need to realize that...
- Okay, so you're taking
the kids to school,
Rose will be here
by the time you get back,
and I'll be home
by noon tomorrow.
What they need
to realize is that
I'm in there every day.
I'm pushing Joe
to get what we need.
I'll miss you, too.
Sometimes our thoughts
are often...
Ed:
Boot time's 48.24 seconds.
Larry:
48? We were
at 39 last month.
Ed: OS memory requirements.
I mean, the thing's basically
doing a 600-pound
standing squat
every time it turns on.
- System response time?
- 403 milliseconds.
There goes
the Doherty Threshold.
- Weight?
- Ed: Only added
a few ounces,
but it puts us
over 15 pounds.
Stan:
It's the extra RAM chips
and the daughter board.
I know what it is.
Loss in compatibility?
Tried to load
Lotus this morning
and it tanked.
I'd call that
a big yes.
All right,
let's talk names.
Oh, you mean software's
not naming it?
I'm gonna take
a list of suggestions
to the product manager
and there's gonna
be a discussion.
So you mean we don't
have a chance in hell.
( all chuckle )
Do you guys have
name suggestions or not?
( taps )
Okay.
Thank you.
Well, if you knew this guy
was locked for a week,
why am I
just cancelling
Kenny today?
It's awful abrupt
and he's not gonna
be thrilled.
My guy's temperamental.
He's an artist.
Despite our back
and forth over the phone,
I wasn't even sure
he would show up.
But now that he's here,
I know he's a yes.
- There's something--
- He say that?
Cameron:
A bunch of teenagers
broke into
Los Alamos National
Lab's computers.
Also into
some cancer center
and a big bank.
Most were DECs
running VMS OS.
God, cover story
and everything.
Pretty cool.
You stole my car.
I stole your keys.
The car just turns on
when I put them in.
Oh, Simon Church.
It's fantastic
to see you.
Thank you for making
the trip all this way.
I can't tell you
how exciting this is
for us and the project.
Right.
Hello to you, too.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I know I've kept you
waiting.
I just have a few things
to get in order.
Would you mind
waiting for us
in the conference room?
I can't wait to see
what you've put together.
- Debbie?
- Mm-hmm.
You think today maybe
we could be adults?
Just for a few hours?
Uh, yes, sir,
Mr. MacMillan, sir.
He is one of the top
industrial designers
in the world.
If he makes our case,
it puts us on a whole
new level.
It was a joke, okay?
I'm sorry. Jesus.
You knew I had
this meeting today.
I'll go first.
The contour,
the design,
the angles, it-- wow.
All I can say is wow.
It's exactly what we wanted.
So glad that
I could accommodate.
I think this is
something very special.
( stammers )
Yeah, it's a pretty girl.
C-can I say something?
What happened to the specs
that you've had for a week?
I saw them, but they
were too limiting.
Moving past the specs
gives us an opportunity
to make something,
something that isn't
just a beige rectangle.
Okay, those rectangles
took months
and months of--
do you think you can just
waltz in here and demand that
we change everything
'cause you don't like
the way that it looks?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Okay, well, we'll redesign
the whole thing to fit the suit.
I saw that you
worked on the Countach
and the DeLorean.
Let me tell you what I know.
Both are in the shop
every hundred miles.
Nobody gives a damn about
what the computer looks like
as long as they work.
Let me tell you
what I know.
Your consumers
will soon have more
than a dozen choices
that look identical
to what you'd build,
so what will capture
their attention?
A design that they will
be magnetically drawn to
every single time they move
to touch your machine.
Joe, this design
will require another
hardware overhaul.
I'm talking hundreds of hours.
The one place that I'm ahead
is heat.
If I ditch the sink
for this, I run--
Joe:
Ahem.
When we unveil the Contrail
and it looks like this,
people will be
falling over themselves.
Wait, the what?
The Contrail.
We're calling it
the Contrail.
I'm announcing it this week,
so don't tell anyone.
The Contrail?
You're naming it
after the exhaust
that comes out of
the back of a plane?
It's about soaring,
leaving the competition
in the dust,
which is exactly what this
design can accomplish.
No, Joe, contrail
is the dust.
Look, if we continue to put
form ahead of function,
we're gonna be the ones
left behind with everyone
laughing at us.
I mean, why don't you
just call it--
call it
the "Cardiff Giant"?
You assured me
that everything
was in line
and that my time
wouldn't be wasted.
I don't have time
to waste.
What is this?
I thought this was
a done deal.
You fly out all this way
and now you're leaving?
I let another designer go
just to take this meeting.
- Simon: What's with the girl?
- Is that what this is about?
- ( elevator bell pings )
- I never should've come.
He's gone.
Are you happy?
All because you
didn't like the name?
What did you
want to call it?
The Giant? Fine.
It's the Giant.
I'll have marketing
toss the art and start
from scratch.
Hey, regardless of the resizing,
half the design was metal.
You want your Armani pants
to catch on fire every time
you put it in your lap?
I think you act like
you can't see it
because the truth is
you can't do it.
( paper thumps )
I read a whole magazine--
thank you.
Someone made me breakfast.
Someone made my kids breakfast.
- It's a revolution.
- ( chuckles )
You must think
I am just the greenest--
No, no, no one I know
gets excited about
business trips anymore.
Especially
this trip.
Why? We're bringing them
fixes for the 99/4A.
- We're part of the solution.
- ( elevator bell pings )
Well, not sure corporate
sees it that way.
These are Band-Aids
on a sucking chest wound.
Well, then why don't we
tell them the truth?
I would, but I'd also
like to keep my job.
- Execs at this level...
- Four, please.
...they want to hear
what they want to hear.
Eight, please.
They asked us
to present the report,
so that's what we're gonna do.
Joanie:
We can play dress-up
and then play Cabbage Patch.
( Haley gasps )
A dance party.
Mommy left lasagna
in the freezer.
We could put it in the oven
and then play Cabbage Patch.
Haley: Or blocks.
We could play blocks.
No one's gonna
tell us what to eat.
We are gonna
make our own dinner
all by ourselves.
- Joanie: Mommy's gonna be mad.
- What are we gonna eat?
Mommy's not here.
We need to get
Ken back.
Are you
shitting me?
We have six weeks
till COMDEX and we
need a case.
Unless you want me to wrap
the machine in a garbage bag,
we need a designer.
With only 256 bytes
of RAM in the register,
we have a bottleneck
that sets off
a four-cycle wait
to clear every time
we load it.
- Hunt--
- Plus a power regulator
that gets so hot,
users refer to it
as the "coffee cup warmer."
Hunt, you're listing off
a lot of problems,
and a lot of problems
means a lot of money
for fixes.
We need assurances
that correcting these
will solve
the computer's flaws
once and for all.
Well, they won't.
I'm sorry, but there are
no once-and-for-all fixes
for the 99.
If you want to do
the right thing,
you drop it
from our product
list for good.
( chuckles )
She's right.
I mean,
what are we gonna do,
slash prices again?
Hand out another rebate?
We're practically giving
it away already.
If you ask me,
we get out of the PC
market altogether.
( elevator bell pings )
I am so sorry.
I didn't mean to jump in--
Donna, they've been
toying with dropping
the 99 for months.
People are
just too scared
to say it out loud.
- Except for you.
- Wait, really?
If you hadn't
said that,
they never would've
heard the truth.
- That took guts.
- I thought it took stupidity.
Will you please
just take the credit?
Now, I say we meet
downstairs for dinner,
on the company's
credit card, of course,
and we celebrate
a job well done.
7:00?
Yeah, okay.
- She had to build
her own fire...
- ( phone ringing )
...and gather
her own wood.
Hello?
Debbie on phone:
Hi, Gordon. I've got
Joe for ya.
But in 1898,
Great-Grandma Iris
picked up
some stakes and ran
off to the Klondike
during the last
great gold rush.
Food was scarce.
You had to hunt
and cook...
...from scratch
all on your own.
But Grandma Iris,
she was tough.
She was real tough.
And this was her
original recipe.
- Are you tough?
- No.
Let her speak
for herself.
Come here.
Show your big sister
what you're made of.
- It's good, Daddy.
- It is good.
I want some.
I'm tough.
- It's good.
- 'Cause you're tough.
And you're tough.
We're all tough.
Can we make
cookies, Daddy?
Mommy has the
cut-and-put-in-the-oven kind.
Can we play
with you, Daddy?
We really
want to play with you.
Yes to cookies,
yes to games,
yes to Daddy's
wonderful stew.
You guys go wash up.
"Heart of the Night"
playing in background
( slow dripping )
"Friendly Communication"
playing on headphones
( door closes )
♪ I'm talking
'bout you... ♪
I take it you're not going
to the photography thing
tonight?
No, actually.
I came to change because
instead I'm joining
John Bosworth
and Ken Burke
at "Strokers."
That's a strip club
with an incredible name.
Beige box it is.
Look, it's not
what I want, either.
Blame Gordon.
He blew it up.
( music continues )
Did you sleep
with Simon?
Is that something
that would be a
problem for you?
I don't give a shit
that he's a man.
Honestly.
10 years ago,
I was at a conference
in Europe.
Simon spoke,
I was in the audience.
He was...
I wanted to be him.
We stayed through
the end of the event,
traveled around
the continent for
the next month
and then...
he left.
That's it.
And yet he was
in the office today.
He's a brilliant
designer.
I was willing
to put up with him
if it meant something great
for the work we've done.
But I guess he was
just stringing me along.
I'm sorry I snapped
at you earlier.
That guy
just messes me up.
( door closes )
- "The Stroke" playing
- Darlin'.
♪ Stroke me, stroke me ♪
♪ Stroke... ♪
That one, she'll dance
for a dollar,
do anything you like.
I don't dance
for a dollar.
Oh, your quote
is perfectly reasonable
and we'd like to move forward.
My quote?
It's gone up.
Way up.
Oh, come on, Kenny, man.
We're not made of money here.
We're talking about
a basic injection mold now.
You and I have been
in the same circles
for years.
I've always had
the utmost respect--
( chuckles )
We was window-shopping
and decided you were
the man to marry.
Yeah, you're settling.
See, I like to get asked
to the prom first.
If I don't,
my feelings get hurt.
Hey, speaking of marriage,
how's Ginnie?
Ginnie's doing
just fine.
Yeah? You line anything
up on the side yet?
Uh, we're not settling.
We're betting on utility.
Your design is simple,
it's welcoming,
it doesn't intimidate,
and we want our machine
to be...
friendly.
Shit, I don't need
to give you a dollar.
You'll dance for free.
( laughs )
( music playing softly )
- Do you have an invite?
- Huh? Yeah.
What the hell
is this?
You skank.
You used me for a ride,
didn't you?
Huh? Relax, there's
free champagne.
30 minutes
and I'm leaving
your skinny ass.
Can I get
one of those, please?
Bleak.
Mm. I think
the photographer
understood very well
how empty this place
really is.
Tell me about it.
I'm from here.
Mm, my apologies, then.
So, what can I do
for "Miss Rainbow Brite"
this evening?
- Agree to build our case.
- ( chuckles )
How old are you?
Old enough to see
the difference between
a $100,000 car
that only a fraction of
the population can afford
and a utility that
every single human being
will be interfacing with
inside of five years.
I can certainly see
why Joe likes you.
Please tell him
I said bravo for the
very clever second push.
Joe didn't send me.
But I know this
is important to him.
Important, hmm?
What did Joe
tell you about me?
Look, I know you guys
humped all over Europe
or whatever.
- And I don't care.
- Oh, is that how he put it?
Because I seem
to remember it
fairly differently.
- Did he tell you
I left him?
- Yeah, he did.
Did he tell you why?
Because I told him
I loved him,
and the moment I said it,
I knew it was over
so I left
the next morning.
I tried to spare myself
the embarrassment.
We did have quite
a bit of fun for a while.
Late nights.
( chuckles )
Did a lot
of stupid things,
but in the end,
I believe Joe
just got bored.
Listen...
I know that you think
what you have with him
is different,
but please don't
make the mistake
of thinking
that he won't
do the same thing
to you eventually.
Come on,
let's go.
Wait, I just got this one.
Come here, come on.
Hey, let's have
some champagne.
Who's that,
an old boyfriend?
Hmm? Yeah.
He looks
like a real asshole.
What did he say to you?
Nothing.
All right,
hold the light steady.
Come on, focus, girls.
Can we play
another game?
Something we can win?
If you play me,
you won't win.
But Mommy
never wins.
That's because Mommy
loses on purpose,
which is not
a good life lesson.
( phone ringing )
In fact, look.
Look what time it is.
It's PJ time.
You guys go get
your PJs on.
All right, as soon
as you brush your teeth,
I'll come in there.
Can we
have our story
in your bed?
Yeah, fine.
Fine, just go.
- Hello.
- Hey, it's me.
Oh, hi.
I-- I called.
Uh, is everything okay?
No, everything's
not okay.
We went over
the case design again today
and once again Joe
wants me to shift everything
around inside to accommodate.
It's style over substance
and I'm tired of it.
Guy comes in and presents
something with metal paneling,
and because of the dimensions,
the heat sink won't fit.
I mean, the thing's gonna end up
being a waffle iron.
I'll fax you over
the dimensions so you can
see how ridiculous it is.
Wait, but that could work,
couldn't it?
Let the exterior paneling
pull heat off the board?
It's actually
an interesting idea.
- ( snaps )
- ( grunts )
( clatters )
( Gordon grunts )
Ooh!
Gordon?
I have to go.
Joanie:
Daddy, we have
our PJs on!
Come on.
( handset clicks )
At the end of the day,
we're happy to be
doing business
with y'all.
We'll get you
a case.
Well, I appreciate
that, Kenny.
The pleasure's ours.
Get that plastic mold
fired up ASAP, huh?
We figure with the amount
of money you're spending,
I can bump you
to the top of the list.
I appreciate that.
Hey, you all right
there, partner?
- Long week.
- Hurts, don't it?
Well, at least we got
to have a good time
on Cardiff's dime,
though, right?
- Yeah, sure.
- Have a good one, Kenny.
Hey, you know, we must'a
seen 20 pretty titties.
Not so much
as a smile from you.
What, are you queer?
( grunts )
That is assault, John!
I will press charges.
I am gonna sue
your ass, John!
You hear me?
Kenny: All right.
I'm good, I'm good.
Get your hands off me.
Can you still make it
work with your guy?
I can try.
Daddy?
Um...
a long time ago,
way back in the 1800s,
there was a farmer
in Cardiff, New York.
Cardiff,
like your job.
Exactly.
And this farmer,
he wanted
to feel special,
so he built
a 10-foot-tall giant
and buried it
out in his field.
And he waited,
and a year went by.
And then he and some
of his workers dug it up.
And the men
who worked for him
were convinced
that the giant was real.
And the people told him
to show it to the world,
and he did.
And people came
from all around.
And he felt
very, very special.
He was so special
that somebody offered
to partner with him.
P.T. Barnum,
an expert salesman.
And they fought
and they argued
day and night
because the salesman
wanted the giant
all to himself.
What happened?
P.T. Barnum
built his own giant.
And he made it
part of his circus
and he claimed
that it was real.
And he was such
an expert salesman
that everyone
forgot about the farmer...
and he was left
in the dust,
in the contrail.
And I swear I was headed
for the firing squad.
Great surprise, huh?
You've been far away.
I'm sorry, I'm...
Ever since Gordon called?
"Music Box Dancer"
playing in background
My husband is--
well, he is
an amazing man.
What he created
for Cardiff,
it's a miracle.
No matter how
they derailed him
along the way,
he made it work
at every step.
Chips on both sides
of the board,
an entire megabyte of RAM
for an expanded OS...
Donna, why are you
telling me this?
Because
we made a deal.
We agreed
that if he did this
that it wouldn't
turn out like last time,
and I just don't think
that he's strong enough
and I'm--
I'm not sure
that I'm strong enough.
You?
You are
incredible.
( music continues )
Gosh, you think
this piano player
knows any other songs?
They should
hire you to play.
They should.
( music stops )
Uh-oh, looks like
he's taking a break.
Good.
- No.
- Go on.
- I can't.
- Quit your stalling.
Fine.
Go on,
get up there.
( applauding )
playing
"New Orleans Boogie"
That's a lot better
than that last guy.
What's your name?
Susan Fairchild.
You call me
all the way out here
just to shoot the breeze?
The PC program's
out of money.
I'm sorry to land it
on you like that.
Wait, why am I just
hearing about this?
What the hell
happened?
Innovation
is a risk.
I don't understand
even what that means.
You sound like Joe,
for Christ's sake.
The good news is
we're weeks away
from a payday.
The moment we debut
at COMDEX, Nathan--
Did you strike Ken Burke
tonight in the face?
- He insulted Ginnie--
- He called me up
madder'n hell.
I need you to personally
offer us a bridge loan
to get us to COMDEX.
Are you
out of your mind?
We're gonna pay you back
by the end of the year.
You have no idea
what these kids
are making, Nathan.
This could change the--
this could change
everything.
In five years,
every one of us
could have one of these
damn things in the house.
It's not a small market
we're talking about.
We gotta get in
the door now.
I'm thinking about
putting up my home.
I need you
to match that.
- Match?
- Yeah.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
Rule number one,
you don't risk
your own money.
You've been
brainwashed,
gone native.
Ain't nothing worse
than a businessman
who's lost his compass.
Hell, Nathan,
you trusted me
before, damn it.
I was the one that
got us to mainframes,
didn't I--
Yeah, that's when you
were still levelheaded,
before you started
burning the bridges
of every
business relationship
that I have ever forged
and now you're
dragging me out here
in the middle of the night...
asking me to cash in
my family's land?
- Jesus, boy.
- Nathan!
If that program
is out of money,
that is God saying,
"Good night and God bless."
Once the last dime goes,
you shut it down.
Pull yourself
together, John.
Go home
to your wife.
The moment I met you,
you know what I longed for?
The day when we would
get to work together,
when we finally
had something that
would be worthy of you.
And that thing
is a portable IBM clone?
Joe, I appreciate
the blanket flattery,
but it's a little
too late, isn't it?
I don't get it.
Why call me?
Why come back into
my life at all?
I remember
when Jeremy said
he was leaving New York
to come spend
a year here.
"Tour the Great Plains,"
he said--
Oklahoma,
Texas, Kansas.
"Photograph the landscape."
What landscape?
I mean, we all thought
he'd gone mad.
But here I am trying to see
what he was talking about,
looking at his pictures,
and trying to figure out
why you moved here.
I'll tell you why.
Equal opportunity,
a level playing field--
Joe, please.
I already got the hard sell
from your wunderkind
over there.
Truly the future
generation, Joe.
She actually reminds me
of you at that age.
She's light-years ahead
of where I was then.
She is tomorrow, and
we're all better off
because of it.
In the end,
it doesn't matter
what design we choose
because it's what's
inside the machine
that's brilliant.
She did that.
Not you, not me.
Do the case,
don't do the case.
I don't care.
Get off me, "Kojak."
Ow!
( goblet crashes )
- ( laughing )
- ( Judie laughing )
All right.
Come here, come on.
Get a hold of yourself.
Sorry.
"That guy just
messes me up."
( laughing )
Oh, wait a minute.
There we go.
You know, you probably
made that piano player
more in tips
than he makes
in a whole year...
"Susan Fairchild."
Wait a minute,
I think I know that name.
Oh, that's my mother's
maiden name.
You probably
heard it around.
No, actually,
I think I read it
somewhere.
Ahem.
You should be
"Susan Fairchild"
more often.
She's fun.
Can I tell you
something personal?
Doing that extra report
got you here.
Saying no
to those execs
changed our whole
presentation.
Showing people
who you really are,
you should do that
more often.
Be bolder.
( elevator bell pings )
Ahem.
I'll see you downstairs
at 6:00 for our flight.
Haley:
Will we find the giant?
Joanie:
I'm sure we're close.
Haley:
We have to dig deeper,
come on.
Joanie:
We're very deep.
Haley:
Oh, my gosh.
I think I found a worm.
Joanie:
You did?
What should we name it?
Haley:
Smiley?
( Haley laughs )
Girls,
what are you doing?
Joanie:
Digging for the giant.
No, honey, it's not
a real giant.
It was real to him.
You said so.
Sweetheart, you gotta
get inside or your mother--
Don't worry, Daddy.
We'll find the giant.
Sweetie,
it's just a story.
Okay, look,
I'll show you.
See? No giant.
Daddy, what happened
to your hand?
Daddy, are you okay?
You guys stay here.
All right?
I'll be right back.
I'm gonna show you.
( knock on door )
I just had to come down.
I was--
Whoa, whoa, what--
what are you doing?
You said "bold."
You said-- wasn't--
I came to bring you
a fax.
Um, the hotel delivered it
to my room by mistake.
I think it's
from your husband.
( gasps )
Oh, my God.
I am so sorry.
I-- you must
think that--
No, no, no.
No, look, these
things happen, okay?
Look, people--
people work together
and they develop,
uh, you know--
they just-- they don't
usually act on them.
Look--
have a good night.
Oh.
( phone beeps )
Hello?
Um, are there any rental car
places still open?
Yes, now.
I need to go home.
( rattles )
( line rings )
( line beeps )
I need you to swing
by my office
first thing
in the morning.
Thank you.
I'll be a minute.
This didn't turn out
the way either one of us
had hoped.
I just wanted
to see you again, Joe.
Spend some time with you
really working on something.
Then I come to find
you're with her.
Yes, I'm with her.
What we had was
10 years ago, Simon.
Stop living
in the past.
Why bother
with any of that now?
I'm sick.
( gasps )
I just came
to say goodbye.
Simon:
Aren't you gonna ask?
What?
If I'm still
gonna do the case?
I know you, Joe.
I know you're thinking it.
I set it up before
I even got on the plane.
I need you to know
that the way
you felt about me,
I wanted to--
Take care of yourself.
( sniffles )
Go.
( bangs )
( door opens, closes )
Are you gonna
get bored of me?
I don't know.
( gasps )
Oh, my God.
Baby?
Baby, is everything okay?
Where's Daddy?
We were in the
back yard digging.
Okay. Okay,
go back to sleep.
Haley:
Hi, Mommy.
We were helping Daddy.
Gordon?
- ( faint scraping )
- Gordon?
Gordon:
Here! Down here!
( scraping continues )
Gordon,
what are you doing?
I'm looking
for the giant.
(music playing )