Man on recording:
Everything that you conceive
of yourself as being
is an illusion.
There is no self.
Take a deep breath in.
( inhales )
Recording:
Allow yourself to
experience everythingness
and nothingness.
As you breathe out,
let go of fear.
You can choose
to leave the familiar...
I'm fine.
Recording:
...or stay in the safe
oblivion
- of pain, ignorance...
- Donna.
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
- Recording: ...and
a blank page.
- Gordon: We need
a lot of shrimp on ice.
- Bosworth: $2,000?
- Gulf white, preferably.
- And not frozen 'cause
people will know.
But two grand for shrimp?
What, are you gonna try
to drown someone in 'em?
- It's crazy.
- Anyone who means anything
throws a lavish party.
At COMDEX,
lavish equals shrimp.
- Did we get
a decent booth location?
- I'm on hold right now.
- Well, how much
is that gonna cost?
- 18 grand.
Whew.
You're not gonna ask me
50 questions?
You gonna
blow the balls
off the numbers?
Yes, sir.
Yes, hello.
That's correct.
27th through the 2nd.
I'm sorry, can you hold?
Maylene, this phone
is clicking now, too.
- Can you get someone
in here to fix it?
- Yes, sir.
Hello, sorry about that.
What is it?
C-23. Thank you.
Commodore, Tandy,
Cardiff Electric.
- ( laughing )
- Gordon: That is huge,
that is huge.
- ( laughs )
- It's so big, I'm telling you.
I've been there.
( groans )
- You all right?
- Uh-huh.
You're not upset
about COMDEX?
What?
Why would I want
to go to COMDEX?
It's just
for salesmen, right?
They can just turn it on
to see what I did.
True.
You know, I'll miss you
while I'm there.
Yeah, me, too.
( both laugh )
You tell
Gordon yet?
I keep putting it off.
You think he'll be upset?
Gordon Clark?
COMDEX.
- Pretty amazing, huh?
- Debbie: I'll take
your word for it.
Well, it's hard to explain
if you haven't actually
been there.
I mean, I don't want
to oversell it or anything,
but it is spectacular.
There's gonna be over
a thousand booths this year.
All the heavy hitters
show up.
You got Steve Jobs, Bill Gates,
Mitch Kapor, you know?
IBM takes over
two hotel floors,
and the party scene--
the party scene
is unbelievable.
Donna and I were there in '81,
we started at the penthouse
and worked our way down,
hitting every corporate party
with decent booths.
You got us rooms
at the Norwick, right?
'Cause staying there
is key,
otherwise you spend
the whole week waiting
in line for a taxi.
Trust me, I know.
I learned the hard way.
Wait, are you going, too?
Joe said
he only needed one room.
You're going
to COMDEX without me?
I'm sorry.
It was arranged the week
you were out sick.
- I forgot to tell you.
- Bullshit you forgot
to tell me!
Cameron's
not going either.
Oh, well, if
Cameron's not going,
then all right, then.
Look, it's not like
your role is essential.
Yeah, I only built
the damn thing, Joe.
COMDEX is about selling it
and that is my area of
expertise.
What about the demo?
What if there's a glitch
in the system?
Like when you
debuted the Symphonic?
I was trying to avoid
bringing it up,
but the fact is,
people still remember
what happened in '81.
I can't afford
to have the stink from that
distracting potential buyers.
But if I need
any troubleshooting,
you're my first call.
I didn't kill myself
all these months
for you to get all
the glory with the Giant.
You plan on seeing me
at booth C-23 on Monday.
( panting )
Recording:
...breathe out,
let go of fear.
You can choose to leave
the familiar or stay...
( bangs )
( theme music playing )
Donna:
Hunt?
What are you
doing here?
Donna, hey.
Uh, um...
- How long have you
been out here?
- Not long.
I was just, um...
( sighs )
- This was a mistake.
- No, no. I just--
- I thought after Lubbock that--
- I shouldn't be here.
Could you just forget
you ever saw me?
Of course.
You don't have to worry.
But you really
can't show up like this.
I know, it won't--
it won't happen again.
I promise.
Donna...
I want you to know
I think you're
an amazing woman.
Everything
all right over there?
Noticed you guys had to
dig up your back lawn
a while back,
resod everything.
Just wanna make sure
there's not some sort
of ugly weed
I need to look out for.
Oh, uh, no.
The heat killed off
some patches.
We just didn't
water enough.
Oh, yeah.
( chuckles )
Gordon:
Donna?
I need to talk to you.
Look, I know
we promise
to discuss any
purchases over $50,
but before you explode,
this was an emergency
situation
and I had
to act fast.
What do you mean,
emergency?
Joe's trying
to box me out of COMDEX
and I don't have to tell
you what a snake he is,
but there was only one
room left on the Strip
and flights to Vegas
were shooting up.
I had to put the $455
charge on our credit card.
I just--
I have to be there.
Whatever
you need to do.
( stammers )
Oh, are-are you sure?
Mm-hmm.
Donna,
you're the best.
Oh, my God.
Thank you.
Oh, I gotta figure out
what suit I need to bring.
Look, I know you think
I look good in blue,
but I don't want
to risk anyone thinking
I'm with IBM, you know?
- Morning, Maylene.
- John...
Now, sweetheart,
you know I can't
talk business
till I get
my "ker-fee" in me.
Nathan, well, I didn't
realize you were coming by.
Can I get you
anything?
Cup of joe.
Maylene knows
how you like it.
I'm fine right here.
Wh-- what
brings you by?
A little while back
you asked me for money
for this PC project.
Oh, you told me to shove it,
if I remember correctly.
Thank goodness you did.
I was able to shift
some things around--
I've reconsidered.
I see.
I thought if my
old pal John Bosworth
wants something
from me,
I should
give it to him.
A little early
in the day for a drink,
ain't it, John?
You havin' fun,
Nathan?
Hey, Boz,
we just got a--
Who the hell do you think
you are, waltzing in here
like this?
- What?
- What is your name again?
- Cameron.
- Get the hell
out of my office, Cameron.
Why do you think
I have a damn secretary?
- Don't make me
say it again!
- All right.
My God, John.
You're a bit jumpy
today, aren't you?
If you don't mind,
I got a meeting.
My main concern
is differentiating this
from the other PC compatibles.
Press will want to lump it in
with all the others.
Well, Cameron's
operating system
is unlike
anything else
on the market.
Cameron?
Uh, yeah,
it's interactive.
Um, I can just
show it to you.
You're barking up
the wrong tree.
No, you want this
machine to stand out
from every other machine
on the floor, you gotta stop
talking about the machine
and you gotta start
talking about the people
that made it.
They bled for this.
The future's coming
whether we like it or not,
but it ain't written anywhere
that it includes any of us.
And getting there ain't free.
There's a cost.
People who put up the money,
they like to take the credit,
but the credit belongs
to them that built it.
This machine
is the future.
Make them see that.
( inhales deeply )
John Bosworth,
you're under arrest.
Can we do this
outside?
- We're gonna
do this right here.
- What the hell's going on?
- Sit down, sir.
- Make sure no one
touches these computers.
Everyone, please be calm
and stay where you are.
We're gonna be shutting
this company down.
Once we have
what we need,
you'll be searched
and cleared to leave.
No company property
will be allowed
to leave the premises.
For now,
just sit tight.
We'll have you outta here
as soon as possible.
Step back from
your keyboards, folks.
Stop typing, please.
Man:
Stay where you are.
Heads up.
( lock clicks )
They think
John did it?
Go try that door
over there.
( knocking )
( clicking, banging )
- Ow. Ah--!
- Do you have a key
to this room?
- Yes.
- ( knocking on door )
( knocking continues )
Come on.
Sir, take your personal
belongings and get out.
- But I--
- Now.
Agent:
Get that out of here.
( typewriter keys
clicking )
He's not in.
I'll tell him
you stopped by.
Oh, no, thank you.
That's fine.
I'll just--
I'll catch up
with him later.
Oh, as long as you're here,
I need you to sign
his goodbye card.
Goodbye card?
You didn't hear?
You two seemed so close.
- Was he--
was he transferred?
- Resigned.
Would've been nice
to have a little notice.
Did he say
where he was going?
Is he leaving Dallas?
He didn't say
and I didn't ask.
( clicking resumes )
( voices overlapping )
- Do you know anything?
- Let's go back to your place,
figure it out.
All right,
I'll see you there.
They're looking for evidence
of hacking, computer crime.
Bosworth couldn't do that.
He knows maybe three people
who could.
Are you
a part of this?
Bosworth
came to me, okay?
He asked if I knew
about the 414s,
about hacking.
It was so easy.
They were practically--
like, the bank has no
security whatsoever.
- ( scoffs )
- I'm sorry.
We were gonna
put all the money back
in Cardiff's account
as soon as we
made some sales and we
came back from COMDEX.
I mean, we thought
he'd never notice.
Everybody out.
Gordon:
It's all a misunderstanding.
Joe:
It's not
a misunderstanding.
We'll be laughing
about this in 24 hours.
Gordon,
you're wrong.
- ( sighs )
- What's going on?
- Did you know about this?
- I didn't know anything
about this.
Yes, you did.
You were involved.
- I was not involved.
- Yes, you were.
- You were involved
from the--
- I did it.
I was trying
to save the company.
We were completely
out of money.
You two are perfect
for each other.
- You're both psychotic.
- If I hadn't done this,
we would've been
shut down weeks ago.
All your work
would've been shelved.
Don't act like
you threw a bake sale.
You robbed a bank.
It was
Cardiff's money.
Once we sold
the computer,
we would've made it
back and then some.
You should've come to me.
We could've made a plan.
Now all of our careers
are in jeopardy.
Your careers?
I could be going to jail.
Oh, my God, you two.
I'm so stupid.
God, I'm stupid.
Stop including me in this.
I'm just as upset as you are.
No, you're gonna come out
on top of this somehow.
Every time something terrible
happens, you seem to benefit.
IBM finding out
we reverse engineered
their PC,
Cameron losing her work
on the BIOS.
- What?
- Oh, yeah.
He crashed it
for publicity and
let you twist in the wind.
Did he fail
to mention that to you
during pillow talk?
Is that true?
I'll bet you're the one
that turned Boz in.
- Now you're top dog.
- Joe, answer me.
Yes, I did it.
For publicity, which we got.
I'm sorry you had a bad day
for the sake of our project.
- "A bad day"?
- Are you really in a place
to cast judgment right now?
And why the hell
are you attacking me, Gordon?
- She stole the money!
- I put my life into that box.
- Like I didn't?
- You gave it a name
and a handle.
You didn't build
a damn thing.
He's right.
You only destroy things.
You've never
created anything.
I created both of you.
( garage door whirring )
So, it's over?
Everything?
We're back to--
we're back
to where we started?
Oh, my God, I--
I can't believe
this is happening again.
Any openings at TI?
Donna,
what do I do?
Gordon, I'm sorry.
I-- I just--
I can't deal
with this right now.
Donna...?
I'm sorry,
I have a meeting.
- Donna?
- ( handset clicks )
- ( sighs )
- ( line hums )
- "Face To Face
With It" playing
- ( Ping-Pong balls bouncing )
I might end up crashing
on my parents' couch again.
I heard he took the money
to pay off gambling debts.
Horse racing.
He's an addict.
Jail should be
a good place to
work on that.
That's why you don't hire
some ancient good old boy
to run your
computer business.
Yo-Yo:
I bet they send him
away for a while.
Coder:
At least he knows where
his meals are coming from
for the next 10 years.
Lev:
You ever talk
to him about code?
- He's like a caveman.
- Yo-Yo: He's a scumbag.
( line ringing )
- Man on phone: Hello?
- Joe MacMillan,
Cardiff Electric.
- How you doing, Jim?
- Oh, hey, Joe.
We gonna see you
out in Vegas this year?
That's just what
I'm calling you about.
I wanted to give you
an opportunity to get in early.
A small order now,
before COMDEX, before
the prices skyrocket.
Ah, I think we're
gonna stick with IBM.
But IBM doesn't
make a portable.
Well, not one
they've announced yet.
Where did you hear
this rumor?
I don't know.
Everybody's talking about it.
- Is there a release date?
- I hear early next year.
- Thank you, Jim.
- Sure. You bet.
- ( cracks )
- ( grunts )
( clatters )
I finally
got them down.
Why don't you
go to sleep,
sweetheart?
You look terrible.
No, I want to wait
until Gordon gets home.
- Has he called yet?
- No.
This kinda thing been
happening a lot since--
Since he dug a hole
in our back yard?
Mom, this kind of thing
has been happening since
the day we met.
I'm just asking,
sweetheart.
Work okay, at least?
Hunt is leaving TI.
Oh, my goodness.
What happened?
- Did he get fired?
- No, he resigned.
- No notice.
- Well, they love him
over there.
Why on earth
would he do a thing
like that?
Mom, I think
I made a mistake.
When we were
in Lubbock...
Something like this
was bound to happen.
Mom, I didn't
sleep with him.
Then what are we
really talking about
here, honey?
I don't know.
I don't know. I just--
I thought-- I thought
he wasn't interested,
but then he was
here last night,
outside the house.
- And?
- Well, nothing, really.
He got all
flustered and left,
and I think he'd been
out there for a while.
Does Gordon know?
Mom, what am I
gonna do?
Your daddy
and I love you,
and we love Gordon
because you love him,
but here you are,
miserable,
continuing to hold up
this entire household
while he's off
God knows where.
We will continue
to support you
and help you
any way we can,
and we'll do so
gladly until we die.
But, Donna, you need
to think long and hard
about why we keep
ending up back here.
And you need
to figure out
what is best
for you and for
your children.
( crickets chirping )
( engine starts )
( tires screech )
( sighs )
What are you
doing?
Hey, honey.
Is that
the Giant?
Yeah, and I also got milk.
I noticed that we were out.
Gordon,
did you steal that?
Isn't that evidence?
No, no, no.
If it was evidence,
they would've seized it.
Gordon, this is not good.
I don't know what
you're thinking, but--
Donna, I need you
to stop looking at me
and thinking,
"Here we go again.
It's the Symphonic
all over again."
- 'Cause it's not, okay?
- Gordon--
Look, Donna, it's not.
I promise.
Look, this--
this right here,
this is shit.
( bangs )
Okay, you were right
to pull the plug.
You were right
to tell your dad
to stop giving us money.
You knew?
How long did you know--
Hey, hey, hey.
Look, I was angry
for a long time,
but I'm not anymore.
You were right.
Okay?
Are you worried about me?
Is that what this is?
Let me do the worrying
this time, okay?
I got this.
I have a plan, all right?
I'm gonna find
Cameron and Joe
and we're gonna
do this together, okay?
I need them.
I can't do this
on my own.
You can't do what
on your own?
Go to COMDEX.
I'm gonna go to COMDEX
and sell the Giant,
just like we'd always
planned.
Damn Nathan Cardiff.
That's crazy.
That's insane.
I love you,
but Cameron is some sort
of wanted criminal now.
- And who knows where--
- I know it's crazy.
I know, but you're
crazy, too.
No, no, you forget that,
but you are.
We were both crazy
and then all of a sudden,
you decided you needed
to be the sane one.
- Yes, because--
- That you needed to take care
of me, but you don't.
Look, be crazy
with me.
I need you to be
behind me, Donna.
I need you
to support me
on this.
I am behind you, Gordon.
You know that I'm here for you.
Thank you.
Listen, the coders think that
Cameron went down to Austin.
If I leave now,
I can make it there
by morning.
Then Joe, then back here
to pack, then COMDEX.
I'm gonna sell
a computer.
My own computer,
just like I always said
I was.
I can promise you
that.
( garage door whirring )
I love you.
( keypad beeping )
( line rings )
- Hello?
- Mom, it's me.
Sweetheart,
what's wrong?
Is everything okay?
The girls and I
need to come and stay
with you for a while.
Okay. Have you talked
to Gordon about this?
Can you just come
pick them up first thing
in the morning?
I'm gonna talk to Gordon
when he gets home
and I don't want them
to be here when I do.
( game beeping )
I got next game.
"What Do You Got
Against Love" playing
God, I would've
paid money
to see you break into
Cardiff Electric.
Does Joe know
it's in your garage?
No, I came
to you first.
Look, I know that we've
had less than an ideal
working relationship,
and I'll take some
of the flak on that.
Yeah, and you've been
kind of a dick to me
outside of work, too.
Well, let's
focus on what we do
have in common.
What if we
take the Giant
to COMDEX anyway?
You know? And orders
start coming in?
I mean, Cardiff
won't turn down
that kind of money.
He'll be forced
to reopen the department.
Why do you even care
if I come?
Because you
are responsible
for half the machine.
We're the talent,
not Joe.
No, I'm in
enough trouble
as it is.
Okay, okay.
Well, it was
worth a shot.
And I want you to know
that even though that we've
had our differences
and I'm not entirely clear
on what the function of
your special OS is,
I'll try and do it
justice at the demo.
I know what you're doing.
It's not gonna work.
Okay, well, let me
make sure I got it.
It's better than MS-DOS
because it does things
like ask you
how your day is going
and corrects you
if you make
a command wrong.
( snaps fingers )
Oh, wait, no,
I know what I'll say.
It's like having
your mother inside
your computer.
How's that?
( thumps )
Come on, Joe.
We know you're in there.
Open up.
( rings doorbell )
He's probably hiding.
Well, what should
we do now?
Take this as a sign
we shouldn't be involved.
Wait, wait, come on.
Do you have 30 grand on you?
'Cause I sure as hell don't,
and right about now
the checks for our booth,
our suite, and our trip
have just bounced.
And if we're really
being honest with each other,
he's not a bad talker.
You have a key.
Shit, he cleared out.
He's gone.
He's not gone,
this is just
how he lives.
On purpose?
God, I know nothing
about this guy.
Other than
he likes glass.
I'm gonna call Donna.
I don't want her to worry.
( phone keys clicking )
( phone ringing )
( sighs )
( ringing continues )
- ( whirring )
- ( ringing continues )
( beeps )
( keys clicking )
( chuckles )
Gordon:
I don't remember.
It's been--
Cameron:
Oh, come on.
I wanna hear about it.
Honestly,
I don't even remember.
I'll tell you
my first time.
- Okay.
- Okay...
it was, um,
the Apple II.
Oh, God, jeez.
I feel so old.
- I'm good.
- All right.
Uh, my mom's new boyfriend
got it for me for Christmas.
Some pathetic attempt
at winning me over.
But by New Year's
I had disassembled it
and reassembled it
four times.
How long did it take you
to disassemble your mom's
new boyfriend?
He hung in there
till Easter.
( both laugh )
You never really
mention your family.
There's not
much to say.
Okay.
Well, it was a few weeks
before Christmas
and I saw the Altair
on the cover of
"Popular Electronics"
and I just
had to get the kit.
But I was in school
and up to my ears
in student loans,
and I'd just spent
my last nickel
on getting
an engagement ring
for Donna,
which cost serious money
I didn't have.
Oh, let me guess.
A big diamond.
Me and Donna used to
write each other these
little love notes,
but they were encrypted.
We--
we developed our own
polyalphabetic cipher...
( chuckles )
Geeks.
Anyways, I designed
the ring myself
and I incorporated
the cipher into it,
and the only way
to break our code
was with Donna's
engagement ring.
( laughs )
Wait, you proposed
to your wife
with a decoder ring?
- I know.
- Gordon, wow.
I was 23, you know?
Anyways, she likes puzzles,
and it was nice, you know?
It was platinum
with sapphires and stuff.
Anyways, I was gonna give it
to her over the holidays.
Well, Christmas Day comes
and I go to get the ring
and it's gone.
You shoulda seen me.
I mean, I tore that apartment
upside down looking for it.
And Donna comes in
with my present
and she's
yelling at me
to stop ransacking
the apartment and open it.
And there it was,
the Altair computer kit.
And I knew she hadn't borrowed
the money from her parents
because she hadn't even
told them about me yet.
Would you believe
that she found
the engagement ring
and pawned it
to get me the Altair?
- Aw.
- And she said to me,
"You can buy me a ring
once we've sold our first PC."
Yeah.
It's hard to imagine
you and Donna ever
being my age.
I got it for her.
What,
the decoder ring?
Yeah, last week.
I knew we were
gonna nail it at COMDEX
and sell the Giant.
So I had the same
jeweler in Berkeley
make one up and send it
out to the office.
It's hidden
in my garage right now.
I'm gonna give it to her
when I get back next week.
Wow.
I hope we sell
the Giant.
We will.
( door opens, closes )
Jesus.
What are you
doing here?
I'm not gonna stay.
I just came to ask
you a question.
You came all the way
to New York to ask me
a question?
It's easier to tell
when you're lying
when I'm looking
right at you.
- Let's have it.
- Is IBM developing
a portable PC?
We are.
So you could crush
my machine?
Crush me?
I had nothing to do with it.
The team's down in Boca.
For once, can you
tell me the truth?
It may come
as a shock to you, Joe,
but you're not
the center of the universe.
Even if I knew you were
making a portable,
you think I could
alter the course
of the aircraft carrier
that is IBM,
make them build one
just so I could hurt you?
You're out
of your mind.
If it makes you
feel better,
we're at least a year
away from market.
Now, if you wanted
to ask me about computers,
you could've called me,
so why don't you have
a seat and let me know
why you're really here?
- I got what I came for.
- Sit down!
Now... let's
start again.
You've been in Dallas
since April.
Where were you
before that?
After you deigned
to tell me the truth,
I drove across the country
to figure out...
am I her son
or your son?
Even if she was dead,
she must've lived
an entire life
after you sent her away.
Places she'd been,
people who knew her.
I talked
to everyone I could,
trying to find
the part of her
that was me.
Oh, Joe.
Do I remind you
of her?
Is that
why you hate me?
I love you.
And I loved
your mother.
You let me think
she abandoned me
and then told me
she was dead
23 years
before she was.
I'm not going
over this again.
I sent her away because
she almost killed you.
And, yes, yes,
I lied to protect you.
She let you fall,
for heaven's sake!
At least she
took me up there.
Because she was high.
She wanted me
to be a dreamer.
Your mother
wasn't a dreamer.
She was lost.
A real dreamer,
someone that matters,
makes something
out of nothing.
And that only happens
with hard work.
You understand that.
You always have.
You're more like me
in that regard,
and thank God.
Now, if you move back,
I'll find a place for you.
You'll be back
on track soon enough.
At IBM?
People have
short memories.
Not me.
Joe, you and I
both know
you have to come back
down to earth eventually.
You're here now.
The hard part's over.
I need to be the primary
on the portable.
Run the whole thing.
That's what you want,
I'll figure it out.
I'm glad
you're back, son.
( door lock clicks )
What are you
doing here?
We came to look
for you last night.
Did you sleep
in my bed?
Yeah, you know,
you should really
get a couch.
You know,
me and Donna have--
Stop, I just came here
to get my things.
You're leaving?
I'm going back to IBM
to build a portable PC
that will actually see
the light of day.
- Are you kidding me?
- It's what I should've
done from the start.
You go back to IBM,
you go back on everything
you stand for.
That'll be you
failing us.
- I just told you I was wrong.
- ( Gordon laughs )
I finally get it.
I finally get how
you operate.
- Great, get out
of my apartment.
- Gordon: No, no.
Throughout this whole thing,
you needed to be in control,
make every decision.
You have everybody
at the company bow
to your will.
But when you're finally faced
with a real opportunity
to be a visionary
and lead in a battle
that's worth fighting for,
you're just
gonna move on.
You know, you can spin
a good word, Joe,
even though you're
not an engineer
and you are certainly
no visionary,
but I never thought
you were a coward.
And you never know
when to shut your mouth!
Gotcha.
Bring that fire
to COMDEX and we'll kill.
- COMDEX?
- Think about it.
How many companies
had their CEO hauled off
in handcuffs last week?
There's over a thousand
exhibitors there.
It's nearly impossible
to stand out in all
that noise,
but people will be lining up
to see the train wreck
that is Cardiff Electric,
and when they do,
we blow them away.
But we don't have
the Giant.
I stole it, took it.
I got it back.
You--
you stole it?
You're crazy.
You're damn right.
Eight months ago,
I was a miserable
sales engineer
whose favorite
part of the day
was clocking out.
Yesterday, I broke into
a crime scene
to steal
the state-of-the-art computer
that I helped create.
Cameron, the brilliant
programmer, months away
from a college degree
and a promising
career in software,
she dropped out,
ended up hacking
into the computers
of a national bank.
John Bosworth,
Texas good ol' boy,
president of the
"I Hate Joe MacMillan"
fan club.
John Bosworth hatched a plan
to embezzle thousands
and thousands of dollars
just to keep
this project alive.
You-- you made us
all crazy,
so don't act like you
suddenly found sanity.
We have the Giant.
It is ready to go.
The only thing
we need is money.
I'm sorry?
We-- we-- we need--
you know...
we need
your money, Joe.
This is all I have.
What?
These clothes, that car,
that's all I have.
I'm sorry, Gordon.
I guess someone was
buying my act after all.
How much
is the car worth?
- Such a beautiful car.
- Let it go.
Look, I'm telling you, Donna,
I'm on a roll.
They're both on board.
I got Joe
to sell his Porsche
so now we've got
enough money for COMDEX.
What's this?
I'm going with you.
You are?
Oh, Donna.
What about the girls?
They're at my parents'.
I guess I am crazy.
Good news--
Donna's coming.
Wonderful.
The more the merrier.
We've gotta make
one last stop before we go.
( raps )
Get inside.
Pretty stupid idea
you coming.
Barry's
your lawyer?
No.
Barry does paperwork,
but he's my friend.
Put up my bail before
I even thought to ask.
They're never
gonna believe
you did this alone.
You don't have
the technical knowledge.
Did you know
that damn bank
was using a DEC-20
running TOPS
for their dial-in
account management
timesharing system?
I kid you not.
Turns out, if you
do it quick enough,
before the exception
handlers are invoked,
you can control-C
out of the user program
and then you're
left sitting with
a terminal session
on an account which has
some pretty interesting
privileges,
including
running Kermit.
( chuckles )
Oh, I had
a good teacher.
Now, why'd you come?
- We're going to COMDEX.
- ( chuckles )
No kidding.
How did you manage that?
It's kind of
a rogue operation.
Well, that's just
as it should be.
I'll be all right.
Oh, come on, now.
Go to COMDEX.
Knock 'em dead.
Do that for me.
Get the hell
outta here.
"Red Eyes" playing
( car engine starts )
Donna:
All right,
everybody ready?
- Joe, Cameron: Yep.
- Gordon: We're good.
We're off to Vegas,
COMDEX!
ed Eyes" playing
Running in the dark
I come to my soul
You can see it
through the dark
It's coming my way
Well, we won't get lost
inside again...