Man on TV:
Cleanup is still under way
in both Galveston and Houston
due to the damage caused
by Hurricane Alicia last week
with storm costs
projected into the billions.
1983 is shaping up to be
the costliest hurricane season
in Texas history.
The death toll
currently stands at 21
with reports
of hundreds injured.
The Red Cross...
( crackling on TV )
- ( Cameron laughs )
- What are you doing?
- Come play with me.
- Play with yourself.
I gotta work.
- You gotta work.
- Joe.
I can't look at code
right now.
Come. It's not as much fun
to beat the computer.
- I want to beat you.
- Why?
It's just better
when you know your enemy.
- Love your enemy.
- Please.
Racing, huh?
( blows raspberry )
- Easy win.
- We'll see.
( game beeping )
- Uh-oh.
- Mm-mm.
Oh, oh, oh!
( kisses )
Joe, that's cheating.
Victory.
Okay, rematch.
- Come on.
- ( chuckling )
Oh, you can't do it,
can you?
You can't just sit and play
for five minutes.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Not right now.
We gotta keep working
on the Giant's new OS.
COMDEX is
closer than we think.
We gotta be ready.
We will be.
Come on,
one more game, please?
Don't play all day.
"Birds Fly" playing
( modems screeching )
( whistles )
Well, good morning,
good morning.
- Good morning.
- Lev: Yo, hey!
Hey, hey, you're getting
that shit everywhere, man.
Uh, pardon our dust,
but expand we must.
- What's going on?
- We're running out
of room for cables.
We're stuffing them
anywhere we can.
- ( buzzing )
- Morning!
- Including the walls.
- Good, great idea.
This guy just opened
with F3.
Why is everyone
bad at chess?
Chess is hard.
I'm hard.
( laughs )
Um, "Parallax"
just crashed again.
Oh, God.
Find out why.
- Lev, how's our speed?
- The networks are lagging
like a bitch.
( typing )
Lots of fritzing out
from overload.
- Man: Heads up!
- I feel like the new
phone lines we installed
should be able
to handle the volume.
No, there's still
delay and drop.
- ( hammering )
- ( saw buzzing )
( Russian accent )
Okay, who put Stormtrooper
in microwave?
Oh, Arki,
I need the aux LAN
online by noon, okay?
- Arki: No problem.
- Oh, God, this is gross.
Hey, Lev,
can we check
the wiring?
Yeah, sure.
I'm redirecting users
over to "Tank Battle"
while we reload
"Parallax."
Give me about
15 minutes.
Getting this thing live again
is like launching a yacht.
Can someone
please deactivate
the top menu item?
I don't want users
blowing the system
trying to enter a game
that isn't there.
I'm blowing the system.
( laughs )
- ( loud crash )
- Yo-Yo: Oh, shit.
What?
What is it?
Dude!
Went through a stud.
- ( sighs )
- Great, there goes
our security deposit.
- ( phone ringing )
- We said good-bye to that
a long time ago, boys.
Mutiny support.
Man on phone:
Hi, my name is Chet Jensen,
user handle KickAssasaurus.
I'd like to report
a programming error
in "Parallax."
The narrow hall
with a bunch of mirrors
has no door.
No, not mirrors,
holograms.
Oh, flummoxing.
But if I say,
"Look at hologram,"
it just says,
"You see an object,
but it isn't real."
- Okay, can you touch it?
- Hmm, no, it says,
"You put
your hand into the light,
but cannot grasp it."
- And there's no way out.
- Okay, well, think about it.
If you can put your hand
in the hologram, what does
that mean?
I mean, you have to think
about the physical space
of the room, you know?
And remember,
the android sorcerer
- is brilliant and cunning.
- ( loud crash )
- Guys!
- Hey, Frosty, don't strip
any more screws, okay?
Gotta-- gotta
make 'em tight,
real tight.
Oh, my God, we have got
to rewire this.
We can't build
the cabinets fast enough.
Wiring's an afterthought.
- Donna: Oh, boy.
- Chet: Wait just a darn minute.
Can I walk through
the hologram?
- Maybe.
- Holy cow!
Whoever came up with that
is brilliant.
Thank you.
I came up with that.
- You're the creator
of "Parallax"?
- Network problem.
- Serious lag.
- That's good,
we're popular.
No, I don't know
that the server host
can handle the strain
or even if the modem bank
can stay up with the load.
- Lev: Then screw
backgammon!
- Thank you.
( men struggling )
Hey, hey, hey.
What is going on here?
You guys,
cut it out.
"Parallax" keeps crashing
because his version of
backgammon is too big.
- No frickin' way!
- Well, how big is it?
Over 500K.
Why does backgammon
have to be half a meg?
It's a square
with some circles
and some triangles.
- It could be
all the colors.
- Color is good.
Hello, our games
have to run on phone lines,
not on a plastic cartridge
with a crap ton of memory.
Yeah, and that's why
they keep sucking.
Look, nothing sucks, okay?
"Parallax" crashes
all the time.
Because you installed
a big-ass version
of backgammon.
Okay, look,
backgammon cannot be
the only reason
that we're having problems,
but until we figure it out,
Yo-Yo, just recode it
and make it grayscale, okay?
Yo-Yo:
What? No way!
( sighs )
What was that about?
I think we should
unplug the cabinets.
Figure out
a better power solution.
Maybe rewiring everything
more carefully will help
with the lag.
( chuckles )
You mean take
the network offline?
- Yeah, for a couple hours.
- We can't do that.
- We're already getting
complaints about the outages.
- It's only gonna get slower
- if we don't figure out
what's wrong.
- Donna, no.
"Birds Fly" playing
in background
( blows )
Whatcha playing?
Another fat-ass game
with color.
( TV turns on )
( all shouting )
( scoffs )
We blew a breaker,
didn't we?
We didn't blow
the breaker.
I think we blew
the whole block.
Going.
( theme music playing )
Man's voice:
Does your work have you feeling
small and insignificant?
Is it as boring
as a hand full of beans?
Add adventure
to your life.
Climb that ladder
and discover the Giant
from Cardiff Electric--
personal, portable,
affordable.
And now introducing
the Giant's golden egg--
the Giant Professional.
Up to three times faster
than the IBM XT.
And with better
graphical capability
than the Apple Macintosh,
the Giant Pro
puts your business
at the top of the stalk.
Good morning,
I'm Chip Rowlett
with "DFW Moneyline,"
and I'm joined
by Gordon Clark,
current president
of Dallas mainstay
firm Cardiff Electric.
Gordon, thanks so much
for being with us today.
Ahem, thanks
for having me, Chip.
Chip:
So what we just saw
was the latest national spot
for two computers designed
over the last two years
- by Cardiff Electric.
- Uh, yes.
And that was
a lot of fun to do--
But personal computing
is only the latest chapter
in Cardiff's history.
In fact, you yourself
were instrumental
in the change
to the business model,
weren't you?
Uh, yes.
Yes, I was--
But now Cardiff
is closing up shop?
Uh, well,
not closing exactly.
I guess we didn't expect
so much success so quickly.
We've been acquired
by a large overseas company.
Chip:
But you will stay on
as president, then?
( whispers )
Hi, could you just--
could you tell him...
Actually, I think
it's time for me to move on.
( whispers )
I need to go
to the power company.
- I need to leave.
- Oh, so, sayonara,
9:00 to 5:00, huh?
Uh, I've given
serious thought
to starting my own
investment firm...
out of my garage.
Interesting.
Why the garage?
Because, Chip,
uh, good ideas
don't come out
of a boardroom, do they?
- ( Chip laughs ) Very good.
- That was good.
- Gotta go.
- Well, Gordon, again,
thanks so much
for being with us.
We've got a lot more
to talk about in the world
of business,
and we'll do that
when we come back
right after this.
Thanks.
Thank you.
- Thanks, Gordon. Good job.
- ( bell rings )
Man:
Okay, we're back in two, guys.
Let's go.
( panting )
( phone ringing )
Hello?
All right.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's good news.
Thank you.
Ah.
- Who was that?
- My attorney.
The sale went through.
- Really?
- They're giving me my share.
- ( laughs )
- That's fantastic, Joe.
I gotta go up
and pick it up tomorrow.
This is good.
You earned this.
You deserve it.
Don't doubt that
for a second.
Just-- just going
back there,
seeing those people...
I know.
You want me
to cancel tonight?
We don't have to have
all these people over.
- No, no.
- We can just
talk it through.
It's a good
distraction, yeah?
( exhales )
10 miles.
- I can tell.
( laughs )
- Okay.
Okay, so I am male.
Uh, I am
in entertainment.
Um, a singer
sometimes, right?
- I'm dead.
- Well, allegedly
you're dead.
Oh, allegedly.
Okay.
Damn it.
Um, okay, let me think.
I am-- oh, oh,
what's his name?
- From "Taxi,"
Andy Kaufman?
- Man: Ah.
- ( cheering )
- Finally!
I was Andy Kaufman.
And I was Big Bird,
so I guess we make
quite the couple.
- ( laughing )
- Evan told me
on the way over here
that you two met
at a planetarium?
You tell it.
All right, well,
um-- well, we knew
each other in school.
We were just friends,
though.
We met in
a rhetoric course.
We argued all the time.
Well, 'cause you were
wrong most of the time.
I mean,
we kind of lost touch
after school.
And as you guys know,
last year was a rough
year for me.
Anyway, this assignment
came through from
"Texas Monthly"
to go profile
Fiske Observatory,
to live up there for a while,
and getting out of town
seemed like a good thing
to me at that point,
so I did, and I started
writing about their
SETI program.
Search for Extraterrestrial
Intelligence.
- Group: Oh...
- Yep, yep.
And so there I was,
searching the skies,
waiting for contact.
- And Joe...
- Woman: Then Joe
walked through the door.
( laughing )
- What do you do, Joe?
- I worked at IBM
for a long time
and then I was
in personal computers
here in Texas.
- And then I got out of it.
- How come?
I needed
to reevaluate.
At the time,
I thought I was unhappy
with the project,
but in hindsight
I realized I was just
unhappy with myself.
So I guess that's
what I've been working on.
Well, Joe is being
very modest.
What he didn't tell you
is he took this
tiny regional company
and turned it into
a national competitor
for PCs almost overnight.
- Wow.
- He's driving up
to Dallas tomorrow
to collect his share
of the company sale.
- But that's not
the whole story.
- No, it-- it's not.
But the outcome
is the same.
So what are you gonna do
with all that dough?
I'm going to start
my own company.
Man:
That's great. Here?
No, in California.
- In Silicon Valley.
- Woman: What?
Oh, you're moving?
Nothing is written
in stone.
But we're
really excited.
My point is,
the past is past,
but tomorrow
is tomorrow.
- This is ridiculous.
- I wonder how often
the power goes out at Atari.
( electric buzz )
- Oh, finally.
- ( scattered cheers )
Okay, what is that?
Uh, Cameron fixed
our power problem.
Yeah, we just ran
extension cords
to the outdoor
sockets next door.
Okay, please
tell me that you asked
the Andersons' permission
to siphon off their meter.
Donna, the Andersons
are loaded.
Think of it
as trickle-down
electricity.
This is a bigger problem
than you might think.
Dallas Power &amp; Light
knows that we overrode
our circuit breaker.
City Planning is probably
on its way with a notice
saying that the house
isn't zoned for commercial use.
We're facing
all kinds of fines,
so it would be really great
if we stop breaking more laws
on top of the ones
we've already broken.
Donna, power is power
and we can handle
the fines, okay?
The only real issue
is the lag
and we can fix that
with more network
equipment and PCs.
I'll call my guy tonight
and see if he has any more
XTs in the warehouse.
- Problem solved.
- Okay, that's a patch,
not a fix.
Yes, which is what we need
to hold us over until we can
fix it for real.
Power company
on line one.
Do you want me?
( sighs )
( TV playing )
- Woman on TV: The winner
is F. Murray Abraham.
- ( cheering on TV )
Shoot, Eddie Murphy
should've won for
"Beverly Hills Cop."
I don't know
who that Salieri is.
That's the whole point.
He's not Mozart.
- Two Shiners.
- Walker Red, rocks.
- Put it on his tab.
- Yeah, we're unemployed.
- Hey, man.
- Hey, Stan.
Don't worry
about those guys.
They're not
actually unemployed.
Larry's interviewing at Tandy
and Ed's likely going to EDS.
He's probably just pissed
'cause he'll be at a place
called "Ed's,"
but he won't own it.
Get it? Ed's?
Yeah, no,
I got it, Stan.
But you have to understand
that we weren't intentionally
trying to damage it--
Hey, they just got
"Dig Dug II" at the arcade.
- Research trip.
- Look, I know that we use
a lot, but-- yes, I'll hold.
( overlapping voices )
Amazing! Hey, guys, wait up.
- Ready to do it?
- Yeah.
- Donna?
- Shotgun!
- Do you want
to go with them?
- What? No.
No, I have to take care
of this anyway.
If you want to go,
you don't have to wait
for them to ask.
You can just go.
Oh, yeah?
Then who's gonna deal
with the power company?
I don't know.
Let them send a bill.
It'll take care of itself.
That's great.
That's a really amazing
system you've discovered.
- Do you have a problem?
- Yeah, Cameron, I do.
You made this a place
without a boss,
and that sounds really nice,
but what that translates into
is a bunch of crap
falling through the cracks
that I end up
having to deal with.
God, well,
if you're so good
at dealing with it,
then why don't you just
keep being the savior
we all supposedly
need so much?
Because I don't want
to be the mom here.
Look, I do that at home.
I came here
to do what I love,
- and I don't love dealing
with the power company.
- Donna.
And I don't love
managing the checkbook
to make sure we don't overdraw
and I don't love playing
wet nurse to a bunch of coders
who act more like
kindergarteners--
Then don't do those things!
Nobody asked you to!
- Jesus.
- Damn it.
I did everything I could
to keep things going,
but Nathan--
Nathan wanted to sell.
You know, I fought
for everyone's jobs,
I really did.
You don't have
to apologize
- for making out like
a bandit in the sale.
- Oh, God.
Man, I'd have done
the same thing if I
were in your shoes.
Before you took over,
I was updating systems
software packages.
After you, we built
two machines in two years
from the ground up.
The Pro was just a Giant
with a bag on the side of it.
The Pro was amazing.
Giant was amazing.
I would never have gotten
the opportunity to do any of it
if it weren't for you.
Gosh, you remember
that one night
when you couldn't
find the music?
- What?
- Remember?
We were three weeks deep
on debugging the Pro.
It was maybe 4:00 AM.
We're in the kill room.
You couldn't focus
because you were convinced
somebody was cranking
"Dream Weaver" in
the parking lot.
- So you go out
to check--
- What?
yeah, you go outside,
you check,
you come back in,
you take a ceiling tile out,
and you climb up
into the ceiling.
Remember?
Come on, it was amazing.
Yeah.
Yeah, I...
sort of.
When was this?
I mean,
I think it was you.
Jesus, we were all
so coked out of our minds
trying to hit
those deadlines.
Who knows?
You know, Donna,
I'm feeling really good
about it.
I mean, this really is
the best way that this chapter
could've ended.
- Can I have--
- Here, cream, two sugars.
- Oh, thank you.
- Now I got time.
And time is such a valuable,
precious resource.
- And now I got
boatloads of it, you know?
- Yeah, that's great.
I can start this
investment thing and--
- Oh, my keys?
- Couch.
- Try the cushion
by the lamp.
- Thank you.
But you know what
I'm gonna spend it on
first is our kids.
And I know I've been
saying that for a long time,
but this time
I really mean it.
I mean, did you know
that Joanie can sing all
the lyrics to "Hey, Jude"?
I mean, I'm sorry,
isn't that incredible?
- Wait, where are the girls?
- It's absolutely phenom--
- they're dressed
and in the car.
- Oh, good.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
The closing--
Gordon, it's today.
- I completely forgot.
- It's okay, it's okay.
Look, I'm just gonna go in.
I'm gonna sign my name.
- It's not a big deal.
- And collect an incredible
amount of money.
You really did it.
You worked so hard.
- I'm really proud of you.
- Yeah.
Look at this.
Their "Tank Battle" round
timed out 15 minutes ago
and they're still
talking to each other
in the chatbox.
Well, I've seen users
do it longer.
They're paying
five bucks an hour
just so they can talk
about what they're doing
over spring break?
Hey, I'm gonna go
meet my XT guy.
- You good?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Good.
( elevator dings )
( sighs )
Of course.
Of course you'd show up
for your piece of the pie.
Unbelievable.
To keep this efficient,
I'll be calling out
shareholders,
starting with
the largest first.
Once you hear your name, please
enter the conference room,
sign the documents
we've laid out for you,
and you'll receive
your checks.
Ronald, Frank,
and Garrett Cardiff.
Did you get my letter?
How was Shangri-la?
It's good.
Healthy.
Lawyer:
Representatives of Sunningdale
Holdings, Limited.
Nathan's making a mistake
selling off so soon.
Company's worth
at least 20% more
than this valuation.
Well, I think it was
a mistake to burn a truck
full of our computers
and then go running off
into the woods.
A lot of mistakes.
A lot, yeah.
The estate
of Nicholas Mundy.
You know, honestly,
I'm just glad it's over.
I mean, last year
was a grind.
I mean, nothing
like it was before.
Although that wasn't
much fun either.
Second machine
was a lateral move.
Less inspired.
The new owners didn't even
want the machines,
they just wanted the patents
so they could build
something better.
The Pro
wasn't that bad.
Not that bad.
We should've put that
on the box.
( both laughing )
Lawyer:
Gordon Clark?
- And... sign right there.
- Ahem.
- Nathan.
- Just sign on page three.
So I can just take this
to the bank?
Yes, that's still
how checks work.
All right, then.
Thanks for the memories.
Lawyer:
Joe MacMillan.
Just sit there.
And just sign
on page three.
( knocks )
This is your cut
minus the first shipment
that you burned.
You get nothing.
Not one red cent.
Now, you go ahead
and you sue my ass
if you want to
because I'd love
nothing better than to tell
a jury what you did here.
You destroy lives.
You cost dozens of good,
honest people their jobs.
You sent my SVP of Sales,
my friend John Bosworth,
to prison,
and for what?
A doorstop of a computer
with a fancy screen
and no legacy.
( huffs )
Some folks say
this sale's a success.
I think my father would've
called it cutting the nuts
off of a bull
and turning it
into a steer.
It's good
you're getting out now.
What?
Something's coming.
It's gonna be big
and it won't include
this place.
And it certainly
won't include you.
You entitled
little bastard.
You just keep going on
believing your own bullshit
if you need to,
but you're always gonna
be the same selfish
son-of-a-bitch rustler
trying to get his.
You stay healthy, Nathan.
So...
what are you gonna do
with your share?
( elevator dings )
I don't know.
You?
I think I'm probably
gonna head back into
the garage, you know?
- Get my hands dirty.
- Good for you.
You're a builder.
That's what you should do.
( elevator dings,
doors open )
Thanks for the letter.
"Pink Turns to Blue"
playing on Walkman
- ( Walkman button clicks )
- ( music stops )
You said that I didn't
have to wait to be asked.
Lev told me
where you were.
He's always late.
Oh, I was just-- I was
supposed to go to dinner
with Gordon to celebrate.
What?
Oh, it's his last day
at Cardiff.
( laughs )
Oh. Wow.
Love to see a wrecking ball
swing through that place.
Oh, here we go.
How do you know
this guy again?
You know, he plays "Parallax,"
sells secondhand equipment.
Fine, he's a fence.
Mamacitas.
The gear is here.
Do you mind if I...?
You said XTs,
I got XTs.
Yeah.
What's with
Mrs. Garrett?
- Excuse me?
- She's cool.
They're both
pretty banged up.
I mean, this one
doesn't have either
of its video cards.
- Yeah,
but we have more, right?
- They're not hard to find.
I'm just saying
that the price should
come down a little.
This is retail,
not wholesale.
Oh, well, technically
they're stolen.
Donna, what is
wrong with you?
You want the XTs or not?
Do you mind
if I plug these in?
- I brought a power inverter.
- Yeah, I do mind.
Yeah, okay,
we'll take them.
Three grand.
( laughs )
Aw, 500.
These things list
for 7,500 each.
Yeah, we're not
paying list.
That's pretty ballsy,
the two of you
out here alone.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here you go.
You ladies look me up
post-Armageddon.
Especially you,
Mrs. Garrett.
( car engine starts )
( computer screeching )
- Well, it sounds
functional.
- Whoa!
- What the hell?
- Hang on. Flashlight.
It's a counterfeit.
Can we still use them?
Can you code in Chinese?
He ripped us off.
( shouts )
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Mommy isn't coming,
is she?
No, Mommy's got
to work late again.
Hey, we could still
go celebrate.
Y'all wanna go get
some ice cream
for dinner?
- ( giggles )
- Y'all wanna go to Braum's?
- Both: Yeah!
- Whatever you want?
- Yes! Yes!
- Yeah, all right!
Let's go.
We'll get
some vanilla ice cream,
- hot fudge,
and bananas.
- Yes!
Daddy,
are we rich now?
I'm not quite sure
how to answer that question,
sweetheart.
Well,
are we millionaires?
Mm, with some
smart investments
in the next
four or five years,
yeah, we certainly
could be.
- Can we buy an elephant?
- Maybe.
- I mean, theoretically.
- So, can we?
Well, you never wanna
get just one elephant.
Elephants are sensitive
creatures and if you
just get one,
then it'll get lonely.
You got to get
at least two elephants.
And, frankly,
sweetheart,
I don't think
we have the room.
If we're rich now,
then why does Mommy
have to work so late?
You know what?
That's a good question.
Daddy, your nose.
- Daddy!
- Hmm?
Oh. Oh, my God.
I'm okay.
I'm okay, girls.
I'll be right back.
( chatter )
Jesus, I remember
the first time I met you,
just a perfect Dillard's
catalogue businesswoman
with big judging eyes.
Oh, I wasn't judging.
I'm just used to
looking at Gordon.
( both laugh )
Oh, where is this asshole?
- You're just
as intimidating.
- No.
You know you are.
You pride yourself on it.
You remember when
we launched the network?
It took
four days straight
to get it live.
It was like raising a barn.
And "Parallax" wouldn't
boot from the menu.
You know, halfway through,
a bunch of us thought it was
never gonna happen.
We were done.
Mutiny was over
before it even started.
But not you.
You didn't give up.
Yeah, well,
it was intense.
So...
you think I should
be the boss.
I think someone should be.
Look, I know
we're doing fine,
but this point right now
is when most companies
like us go under.
We're plateauing.
We need to grow in a big way
or we're not gonna make it.
Okay, well,
we can't let that happen.
We're in dire need
of some major essentials.
We need more users.
Our subscriptions
have topped out.
We need another game.
We haven't put anything
out in, what, six months.
Yes, I know, Donna,
but I need to wait
for the right idea.
And we need
to expand the network
because buying stolen XTs
isn't gonna cut it anymore.
You're right.
You're-- yes,
you're totally right.
But here's the thing.
I--
I'm not interested
in being in charge.
I want to work,
I want to do my thing.
I'm not interested
in product managing.
Well, I'm not either.
( groans )
Look, I've been
watching people chat
on the network
while they're playing,
sometimes even after
for hours on end,
and I think there's
a real opportunity
for a community to exist
outside the games.
So if you just help me
with the managerial side,
then I can
play around with that
and still keep my hands
in the guts of the network
and I'm a happy camper.
( door closes )
Son of a bitch.
Hey, dickhead.
Those computers you sold us
were counterfeits.
Bummer.
We want our money back.
- Sorry, ladies.
- Uh, no, 500 on the bar now.
Come here.
- Joe!
- Okay!
Okay, okay, we're sorry
we bothered you.
Good-bye.
Okay.
Well, I think
we pushed our luck about
as far as it's gonna go.
What?
How did you--?
Hey, that little shit
has two brand-new XTs
back here in boxes.
What?!
Leave the money,
just grab the gear.
Open the trunk!
Give it to me.
Okay, I got it.
Hey!
Scavengers!
Hey, you still
want my number?
What the hell?
( door opens )
- Hey.
You all right?
Yep.
What happened
to your nose?
- Allergies.
- Mm.
Gordon:
We missed you at dinner.
- I know, I'm sorry.
- It's fine.
We'll just go out
next time I sell a company.
- Are you drunk?
- I'm fine.
Work just went--
oh, I don't know.
Work went insane.
I got you a slice
of Braum's pecan pie.
- Oh.
- It's in the fridge.
Thanks. You mind
if I just save it?
I'm exhausted.
I'm gonna go crash.
Yeah, sure.
Hey, Donna?
Yeah?
- This is good, right?
- Hmm?
Selling Cardiff,
you know, moving on.
Right?
Yeah, it's very good.
Yeah, I just...
And besides,
it wasn't up to you.
Hey.
I was getting worried.
Did everything
go okay?
At dinner last night...
do you believe those things
you said about me?
Of course I do.
Yes, I left
some details out.
I didn't say
that you hurt
a lot of people
or that you lied your way
through the door,
but you made that company
what it is today.
I didn't get the money.
They shut me out.
Well, we don't
need the money.
Marry me.
What?
- Why?
- Because I love you.
Or because I was
the first person
to forgive you?
I get that you're scared.
You've been down
this road before.
( laughs, grunts )
Marry me.
Yes.
( keyboard keys clacking )
- ( video game gunfire )
- ( keyboard keys clacking )
( video game explosion )
"The Old Man Down the Road"
playing
He take the thunder
from the mountain
He take the lightning
from the sky
He bring a strong man
to his begging knee
He make the young girl's
mama cry
You've got
to hidey-hide
to jump and run
-  You've got to
hidey-hidey-hide...
- ( door buzzes )
The old man
is down the road...
- ( laughing )
-  The old man
Is down the road...
( instrumental music
playing )