( planes roaring
in distance )
Heli-skiing in Bulgaria.
The chalet I stayed at
had beds like a Soviet prison.
But the snow--
oh, my God.
- Was your first job in oil?
- Hell, no.
My parents ran
a carpet store.
Worked there
into my 20s.
Oil was just
a stain to me.
Well, not to mention
that his main ambition
was bringing girls there
after hours.
Remind me to kill my brother
for ever telling you that story.
- ( both laugh )
- What derailed
those big plans?
Well, there comes a time
when a man's gotta strike
out on his own.
- Store burned down.
- Okay, that, too.
So, at 26,
unskilled,
I set out
to eat the world
for breakfast.
The only job I could find
was managing the sludge
from a rubber plant
just outside of Cleveland.
My boss had me cut some corners
and the river caught fire.
- Cuyahoga River?
- 'Course I got fired anyway,
even though I just
worked for the guy
who was working
for the guy.
- The point being--
- It's always better
to be the guy.
That's my usual joke,
sweetheart,
but just to show
I can surprise you,
the point being
we all have to take our lumps
before we come into our own.
Makes getting there
all the more sweet.
So, you're in love
with my daughter, huh?
- Dad.
- What, you don't want
to know the answer?
Okay, he's impossible.
Just ignore him.
And she's an apple
from the tree.
Okay, I'm gonna go
say hello to Graham,
spare myself
the torture.
Get him to do
some work for a change.
He's supposed to be
fixing my Jeep.
I love your daughter
very much
because,
among other things,
she's skeptical, like you.
Then you won't mind
me asking you how you
intend to support her.
She won't accept
any help from me,
at least not
while I'm alive.
And the money
she makes from writing
is gonna be spread
pretty thin for two.
Don't worry,
I'm considering
several options.
- What about oil?
- ( chuckles )
Oil's all about
digging in the past.
I've never been
that interested.
Powering the world
isn't interesting
enough for you?
With a glut
on the horizon,
innovation's
bound to be slow.
If I were you,
I would be looking
to diversify.
Into what?
Something
forward-looking
with the potential
to change everything.
For me,
that's still tech
and will be
until proven otherwise.
Here's what
I think, Joe.
I think with your
checkered work history--
and that's the nice way
of putting all the things
I've heard--
you don't have a whole lot
of options right now,
in tech
or anywhere else.
With your
abysmal references,
I think you'd have
a tough time getting a job
selling waffle irons.
You'd really want to put
yourself through all that?
- Whatever it takes.
- I'm just stating
cold facts.
You won't easily
get a new job.
If I haven't
made myself clear,
I'm offering you one.
I don't know
who you think I am,
but I'm not
looking for charity.
And I'm not looking
to give it.
Today-- today
is dream lab day.
I'm gonna really
set 'er up, you know.
No more talking,
just action.
You know, I may
even teach myself C.
Who says
I'm only hardware?
Oh, in my spare time,
I really want to learn
to cook.
Like, you know,
really cook,
you know,
for all for us.
Any special requests
tonight, dear wife?
Huh?
Duck à l'orange?
Yeah, what?
Did you find
the crunchy--
- Hey, you okay?
- Yeah.
I mean, sort of.
I went to the bank yesterday
to try and increase Mutiny's
credit limit.
The guy there
just laughed at me.
Well, uh,
how much you need?
Ha-ha, you couldn't
afford it.
Well, that's what
schmancy VCs are for.
Yeah, well,
if we can close him.
( groans )
I'm afraid without
longer term data
- he'll balk
at our projected growth.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Look, you always killed
your presentations at TI.
This is gonna be no different.
You just go in there,
you tell a good story
with confidence.
- Haley: Daddy!
- Oh, you know, you'd think
the house was on fire.
Flying in, babe!
( imitates airplane roar )
It has to be
re-entrant, recursive.
I mean, you never
need to branch
except to sequence,
select, or iterate.
- I don't--
- I'm trying to help
the graphics.
What, even if it makes
the network crash?
Do another rev in blocks,
and do it by tonight.
- Cameron, it's up.
- Yo-Yo: Fine.
What?
Why is this sequence
not done?
Cameron, we're live.
What?
Stand-alone messaging,
no game.
We're calling it
Mutiny Community,
but we're open
to something snappier.
How many hours
did this take you?
Not too many.
Donna, we talked
about this.
You can try this,
but we're falling
behind on games.
Wait, wait, shut up, shut up.
Look, our first user.
"No game, just chat.
Hi, how are you?"
( music continues )
Okay, can you please go
finish your game code now,
like what we actually do
at this company?
( door closes )
Oh, God.
I didn't expect a ticker tape,
but I could use a chair.
- ( grunts )
- ( music stops )
Oh, God.
Whoo, Jesus.
The first prison riot,
I broke both my ankles.
I shattered them.
They got me with
the water cannon.
They blasted me off
a second-story catwalk.
Pow!
Right on the concrete.
God dang, are you guys
buying any of that?
- ( all laughing )
- Jesus, what's wrong
with you?
How you doing, Bosworth?
Arki, meet a legend.
( speaks Russian )
- Yeah, sure, sure.
- When'd you get out, Boz?
Well, I tunneled out
a couple days ago,
by God,
but, uh, just had
to find me a shower.
I'm ready to go.
Come on, let's get
the party started.
- Where do I sit?
- Wait, you're working
here now?
- Awesome!
- Yes, sir. Just signed on
as employee number 17.
Yo-Yo:
Did you learn how to type
while you were in prison?
( Bosworth laughs )
You son of a bitch.
It's good here?
I'll sit there, for God's sake.
( theme music playing )
You have
nosebleeds before?
No, not since
Garrett Faloona
used to punch me
on the playground.
You have
any other symptoms--
headache, nausea,
soreness of the joints,
anything?
No, no, not really.
I mean, I, um...
Back when we were chasing
deadlines on this computer
we were building,
mm, I used cocaine
for a brief spurt.
Okay.
How brief and how much?
Two, three months.
And, I don't know,
whenever we needed it.
We were
under the gun, so...
Cocaine is a tropane
alkaloid that can burn
your nasal membranes
if you don't die
from a heart attack
or a stroke first.
N-n-no, I stopped cold
three months ago. I'm--
Good. I'd hate to see
your daughters grow up
fatherless.
That would be sad.
Well...
no, I'm not
one of those people
that gets addicted
to stuff easily.
I can promise you that.
( sniffles )
You could've
at least told me.
What? We're both
sick of playing boss.
I mean, as soon
as he gets up to speed,
he can take stuff
off our plates.
- He ran Cardiff
for 22 years.
- I know.
Mutiny is not Cardiff.
That's the whole point.
- I know.
- Cameron,
he's an ex-convict,
which is not exactly
the smartest hire
when we're in the market
for more funding.
And when we're
this strapped for cash,
you're gonna waste it
on somebody
that doesn't know a bitmap
from a baud rate?
Don't do this.
Don't threaten
what we're building here
out of guilt
or feeling sorry for him.
Donna, he stays.
We talked about being
in this together.
We talked about
communication being key.
This-- this isn't
what we talked about.
"That Was Close; Diversion
Eight, Diversion Two, Closet,
Close-Up, Close [to the Edit],
Closed" playing
♪ Hey... ♪
( grunts )
( music continues )
♪ Hey... ♪
( snorts )
- ( music playing
in background )
- Ah.
( both sigh )
What?
I was just
thinking about...
your father offering
me that job.
( laughs )
Yeah.
I mean, I'm still
mad at him.
It's the classic
Jacob Wheeler ambush.
What if I took it?
Well, why would you?
I mean, we joked about that.
You called that place
a mausoleum,
"a business literally
built on fossils."
I know, but, I don't know--
I've been doing a bunch
of reading.
3-D computer modeling
is really shaking up
the industry,
changing where
and how to drill.
I could get into that,
help take Westgroup
into the future.
What about
those other jobs?
Didn't pan out.
I know, that's no reason
to go work for your father's
oil company,
but I've kicked the tires
on this, Sara,
and I'm genuinely
interested.
Or maybe you're
just tired of waiting.
( scoffs, sighs )
I'm sorry.
Look, I know
that this past year
being on the sidelines
has been really tough
for you.
But when you said you
were waiting for contact,
I didn't think you meant
from my father.
If this is
too weird for you,
then I can wait around
for something else to--
No, no.
I don't want you
to be unhappy.
And we'd have
to move to Dallas.
Would that make you
unhappy?
Joe...
if you want
the job,
this job,
take it.
Of course,
"I Am the Fly" playing
♪ Crawling ♪
♪ Over your window,
you think I'm confused ♪
♪ I'm waiting
for the divergent wasp ♪
♪ To complete
my current ruse ♪
♪ But there's
an air-pellet hole... ♪
- ( line ringing )
- ♪ I can crawl through
to you... ♪
( modem screeching )
- Stop!
- "...revenue, our monthly
burn rate is actually--"
Watch out!
Oh, Donna, I'm sorry.
- Guys.
- I was aiming
for that mongrel. Ah!
- Guys, just take it outside.
- Cube not okay. Where is it?
- ( murmuring )
- Donna, it's your husband.
Hi, Gordon.
- You hear that?
- ( modem screeching )
- Guess what I'm doing.
- Um, using a modem?
Aha, but how?
Could it be that I got
a second phone line
so that we could go online
and talk at the same time?
Yeah, that's--
that's probably it.
- How'd your VC meeting go?
- Uh, it's in an hour,
which is--
- look, Gordon, I've gotta go.
- Yeah, well, you wanna
run your pitch by me?
Or maybe I could, uh,
you know, help out and--
Really, I'm sorry.
I love you, darling.
I'll see you
at home, okay?
- Oh...
- ( dial tone humming )
( keyboard clacking )
( game beeping, pinging )
- ( game explosion )
- Oh. ( laughs )
All right.
You wanna play,
little man, huh?
( beeping, pinging )
What? No!
There's no way
you shot first.
I shot 100 milliseconds
after the game started.
- Stan on phone: Hello?
- Stan, it's Gordo.
What are you doing
right now?
( phone ringing )
( elevator dings )
Oh, good,
I'm not late.
Yo-Yo tripped over
a surge protector,
sent three XTs flying.
Luckily,
a stack of pizza boxes
broke their fall.
Saved by squalor.
- What?
- You changed into that?
- Yeah, I--
- Was I supposed
to dress like that?
Well, was I supposed
to dress down?
Oh, God, maybe you're right.
Maybe they want young
and rebellious.
Yeah, or maybe
they don't invest
a million bucks in you
if you've got holes
in your jeans.
Damn it,
I could've--
Excuse me, Miss Howe,
Miss Clark?
Mr. Bondham
will see you now.
Okay, so you have put up
chess, checkers, backgammon,
"Tank Battle,"
and "Parallax."
And ignoring the first three
because who cares about those?
That's two games
in 15 months.
Not exactly
in a hurry, are we?
Well, "Parallax" actually
has 21 chapters,
each one with
a totally different world.
- So it's not--
- Yeah, my nephew
got hooked on it.
- That's why I took
this meeting.
- Cool.
But then he got bored
around chapter, uh, 13
- when the giant
ice squids...
- Crabs.
...ate the Eskimo palace
or whatever.
He said it's fun to play
with other people,
but the game itself--
you know, pfft.
It's nowhere near as good
as what Atari's been
popping out.
I think if your nephew
understood coding
a little better,
- he'd think "Parallax"
was pretty cool.
- Ahem.
Um, look, cartridge games
may look better for a while,
but online gaming
is the future.
Only if there's a profitable
way to sustain it.
That's exactly right.
And that's why we're here.
Our network is overloaded,
limiting our ability to
sign up new subscribers.
How do you even know
they're out there?
Only 10% of Americans
have computers.
Only 15% of them
have modems.
Not to mention the fact
that you're only
on Commodores.
I mean,
how do you really know
that there are
enough users out there
to make us all a killing?
We just do.
I mean, in-store inquiries,
word of mouth.
There's a whole
world of data.
Oh, yeah,
with proof like that,
how can I argue with you?
Look, Mr. Bondham,
if we had the capital
to buy 10 11/750s--
- 35 grand a pop, used.
- 32-- 32, plus additional
funding to cover operations
through the end
of the fiscal year,
then I think--
What about kids?
- Hmm?
- Excuse me?
Do you have or want kids?
- No.
- I have two.
What does that
have to do with it?
Well, when I invest
in a company,
I don't just bet on an idea,
I bet on the people.
Success is no Sunday drive.
It's not another to-do
tacked to the fridge.
If you two, as you claim,
are really gonna run
this business,
I need to know that
you're fully committed,
long-term.
Even over, you know,
biological imperatives.
Sorry, are you gonna
give us the money or not?
( sighs )
( elevator dings )
Joe MacMillan?
Yeah, uh, hello.
Hey, Eugene Bowdich.
Welcome to Data Entry.
I'll show you
to your desk.
I was on 23
for orientation
and HR told me
to come down to B2
and I think
there's been a mistake.
Oh, no mistake.
You're on my clipboard.
Now, Westgroup Energy,
if you're not aware,
is really
a parent corporation
to nine wholly owned
subsidiaries,
and we do DE
for all of them.
Color-coded baskets,
redundantly labeled,
correspond
to different inputs.
The process of digitizing
the company's records
was begun in 1974,
though clearly since then
we've made great strides.
Does Jacob know this
is what I'm working on?
You mean Jacob Wheeler?
Uh, never mind.
All right,
any questions?
So, it's--
it's just--
it's, uh...
d-done by hand?
Oh, no, we use optical
character recognition,
which-- which
we correct by hand.
For particularly
naughty images,
you might even get to use
the Big Kahuna over there.
But you'll have
to ask me first, okay?
Okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
Please clock out
at the end of your shift,
and we labor to keep
the bathrooms tidy.
I trust you'll comply.
( door opens )
( game laser zapping )
Die, die, die,
you disgusting pig dog!
Eat it! Eat it!
Jeez, Gordon,
you're gonna break
the keyboard.
- ( game explosion )
- You see? Right there.
You should be dead,
not me.
It's like the timing's off
or something.
Here, come on,
let's go again.
There's more
in the drawer.
No, thanks.
I'm surprised
you're still--
I mean, I thought
it was just a goof
when we were finishing
the Giant Pro.
It was, Stan, jeez.
Look, I found some
left over.
What am I supposed to do,
throw it away?
You know?
Come on, let's just play.
Okay, wait--
hey, this time,
okay, on three,
fire your tank.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Damn it!
What is going on here?
I mean, we--
something's going-- we both
saw that I fired first.
I mean, there's gotta
be some sort of glitch
or something in the--
Why don't we take a break?
Maybe grab a beer?
No, I gotta call Donna
and tell her about this.
I mean, this is one
of their flagship games.
- ( modem screeching )
- Oh, heh.
Duh, we're using
both lines.
( blows raspberry )
Uh, well, I guess
I'll just go over there.
- You okay to drive?
- Yeah, of course I'm
okay to drive.
Oh, shit!
Stan, will you
help me out?
Will you go pick up
the girls from school?
- What? No.
- What do you mean no?
I mean, I haven't seen 'em
in, like, two years.
( sighs )
Well, here, look.
You can figure it out.
Here, and feel free
to buy 'em some snacks
or something.
- ( sighs )
- ( door opens, closes )
( muffled music playing )
( music continues )
( laughing )
He touched the soap.
Very clever, ladies.
Very clever.
( laughing continues )
Man, that was awesome.
Did you see the look
on his face?
- Man: Yeah, perfect.
- Man #2: Priceless.
That's a fire hazard.
- Hey, where's Donna?
- Whoa, look who's here.
Shouldn't you be in Tahiti
or something with all the money
you just made?
Look, there's a major
problem with "Tank Battle."
The game's not fair.
Dude, we've got
bigger headaches
right now.
And it's a good thing
Cameron isn't here.
Oh, yeah, lucky me.
Listen, there's times
when I fire at my opponent
and the game doesn't
read it and I get killed.
Oh, wow, well,
couldn't it be that you're
just shooting second?
No, Stan and I fired
at the same time
over and over
and even when I cheated,
the results were random.
Hey.
( knocks )
Your system's reading inputs
from multiple modems, right?
- Duh.
- So in a given game cycle,
the token checks them
one at a time
to see who fired
their tank.
- We know this, man.
- Okay?
And if you're saying
whoever's fire command
happens to be next in line
when the token sweeps it
is awarded the kill,
then you're right.
Congratulations.
But every user shares
that hazard equally.
But it doesn't
reflect who shot first.
I mean, it's random.
What's the point
of playing a game
if the outcome is random?
Look,
it doesn't matter, okay?
I got a fix for ya.
( clicks tongue )
Aren't you just
the hardware guy?
Well, I'm also degree-
in-computer-science-
from-Berkeley guy,
where Donna went,
with honors and top grades
that'd make your penis shrivel,
so maybe if you shut up
for a second, you could
learn something.
You time-stamp the input
from each individual modem
and at the end of each
complete token pass.
You put them
in the correct time sequence
before you execute them.
- That way,
whoever shot first...
- ( phone ringing )
( pops lips )
...wins.
- That's solid.
- That is not dumb.
We should, uh--
we should do that.
Um, g-guys, find Donna.
Someone tried
to kidnap her kids.
Damn it, Stan.
Give me the phone.
It's, uh,
Gordon Clark here.
Yeah, I see.
Actually, that was a friend
of mine that I asked to--
yeah, we're supposed
to call first.
Well, I'm--
I'm sorry for the trouble,
Principal Hawkins.
Oh, no, no, no.
I'll be right there.
Pizza deliveries
for a week if not
a single word.
A month, plus soda.
I can take heat from my wife,
I'd just prefer not to.
- Two months.
- Look, one month, okay?
Deal, you little rats.
I mean, they don't want
what's next or vision,
they want an Adam's apple.
Well, at least what we wore
didn't matter.
Hey.
There's been some
prankin' going on, sure.
- Cameron?
- What?
You should see this.
Lev:
We might be in trouble.
( conversation continues
indistinctly )
( door closes )
They had a power fraz
about an hour ago,
fried a connector
or some such.
You might want to go
take a look at that.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah.
It's exactly
like our "Parallax,"
except with better graphics.
I can see that.
Where did you get this?
A friend of a friend
copied it from his friend,
free.
Some asshole
ripped off "Parallax"
and is just giving it away.
- He hacked into our network?
- I don't-- look, here.
Who did this?
Do we know?
Some dude. No one knows him,
but supposedly he signed it
in the comments
to his final subroutine.
( laughs )
Tom Rendon.
Okay, check the list.
See if he's a subscriber.
Rendon, T.
Holy shit.
2123 Clarendon Street.
He's even still logging on.
Hey!
Hey, Tom Rendon?
- Who are you?
- Hey, we're the people
whose game you stole.
- Oh, Mutiny.
- Uh-huh.
Very cool.
I was kind of hoping
it would find
its way to you guys.
What'd you think?
- Mr. Rendon--
- Tom.
Mr. Rendon, we appreciate
your business
for the last 10 months,
but you can't just
copy our game
and expect
to get away with it.
Well, I didn't
just copy "Parallax,"
I made it a whole lot better,
and if I wanted to get
away with it,
I might've, you know,
not s-- not signed it.
My point is you have
to stop or we'll be forced
to take legal action.
Oh, okay.
All right.
Well, I run IT at
Chatham &amp; Watkins downtown,
so I can help you
find a good lawyer.
Oh, you think
this is a joke?
What, you think a couple
of girls won't sue your ass
into the ground?
No.
You won't sue me
because then you're
gonna make me mad
and then I'm not gonna
tell you how to make
your game better.
- You guys wanna come in?
We could have a couple beers.
- Okay.
- I can lay
everything out for you.
- Listen, you might think
you made the game better,
but we do games online.
Yes, six colors,
that fluid scan, it might
work on a Commodore,
- but if you want
to do it across phone--
- I get it! I get it.
I get it.
You don't want
to use spaghetti code,
you want to make
more with less.
That's the real art
of it.
Have you ever tried
page flipping, dithering?
- No, I'm new to coding.
- Combined with anti-aliasing?
Don't do it all on C.
You'll also cut back
on memory.
( sighs )
Beer offer still stands
if you want that tutorial.
Okay, look, just don't
do it again, okay?
Or we're gonna have
a serious problem.
Yes, ma'ams.
Mea culpa.
I hereby cancel
my subscription.
Mm, I don't even
want this anymore.
Dudes, mother lode.
It's to Cameron
from Boz.
Bet it's the last one
he sent from jail.
- What are you
gonna do with it?
- What do you think?
Boz went out for smokes.
Wait, won't that ruin it?
I can fix it.
Did it to my sisters
for 13 years.
( speaks Russian )
Come on.
Yo-Yo: Nice.
( imitating Bosworth's voice )
"Dear Cameron..."
- ( all laugh )
- "...I'll keep this short
'cause I know or hope
I'll see you soon.
More of the same
with Johnson.
I won't burden you again
with that whole mess.
I'm just trying
to put it behind me."
Oh! Cue appropriate
butt sex joke.
( all laugh )
"I think about
my wife, Cameron.
Ex-wife, I mean.
And I think about my sons,
if they'll know me
when I get out
and, God,
if they'll want to.
That's what
hurts the most.
That's the real knife
to my heart."
- Hey, uh, maybe
we should stop.
- Why? It's too good.
Yeah, man,
let's just forget it.
- ( scoffs )
- Bosworth: Go on.
Finish it.
Go on.
( normal voice )
"Was what I did worth it?
Honestly, I think so.
Am I good
in the eyes of God?
Maybe this is terrible,
but I don't really care.
It's me inside
that matters, not Him,
push come to shove.
Sorry to lay
all this on you,
but you're all I got
to talk to,
the light
in this dark hole.
Boz."
What the hell
are you doing?
We were just
goofing off.
Get out of here.
Go home.
This is where I live.
Then go someplace
I can't see you for
a long time, okay?
( door opens, closes )
You know, we really
work well together.
Maybe we should
start another project.
Maybe I could
even fund it.
At least till it gets
off the ground.
- You'd do that?
- Yeah, why not?
Man, that'd be sweet.
But I'm headed up
to good old NorCal.
But-- California?
Do you have a job
lined up?
Nope, just rolling
the dice.
Booked my ticket the day
I got my pink slip
at Cardiff.
Mm.
A lot of big dogs
out there, Stanny.
You know,
eat or be eaten.
Yeah, well, good,
'cause I'm hungry.
- Ruff, ruff,
you other mutts.
- ( chuckles )
Ah, you don't need
a partner, Gordo.
I'm sure whatever
you dream up will
be incredible.
L-let's play
another round.
I'm sure they've
got it recoded by now.
All right, on three.
No cheating this time.
All right,
line 'em up.
Ready?
Both:
One, two, three.
Why the lag?
That's weird.
Low user volume,
each on
a dedicated line?
I mean, the delay
should be imperceptible.
Nothing near this bad.
I wouldn't pay
for this crap.
The idiots
must've messed it up.
Now the game
sucks even more.
Amit and Wonderboy:
One, two, three.
I don't understand.
The new time-stamp code
should only take an extra
100 milliseconds, tops.
How many users
we got online?
- 132.
- Uh, yeah,
check again, dumbass.
- I'm showing 80 live modems.
- Lev: Wait a second, hold it.
There's code in here
that we didn't write.
What?
What's going on?
Someone hacked
into "Tank Battle."
They added bytes that
let multiple users
play on a single
phone line.
( laughs )
This is awesome.
Like a kid when he buys
a movie ticket
and then passes it
back to his friends.
How many hacks
are there like this?
Here's one that's allowing
12 users on a single line.
12-- wait, what?
How did this happen?
Do you guys
have back doors
in your code?
- Yeah, we always use some--
- Did you tell anyone
about them?
No, no, of course not.
Okay, look, look, just--
we'll delete the bytes.
No free rides.
And then we'll talk
about security.
Wait, wait, hold on.
If the hacks are from a user,
I think I can trace them.
( knock on door )
How'd you do it?
- What?
- No, just tell me, okay?
You stole money
out of my pocket
by getting 12 modems
to share a single phone line.
You owe me
how you did it.
I built a PBX in software,
my own private branch exchange.
And 12 is nothing.
I'm working on
three times that.
If Mutiny could do that,
it would make
our overhead per user
that many times smaller.
You do that
in your head?
You want to know
what I think?
If it doesn't
take too long
'cause I really
don't want to burn
my chicken.
You're good at this.
I mean, you could be
hacking into anyone.
But are you?
CompuServe? GEnie?
I don't think so.
I mean, I think
you're only cloning our games
and hacking our network.
So either you spend
all your time hating us
or you really love
what we do.
- Who says it takes
that much time?
- I do.
I checked our top-10 users
last month based on hours
spent online.
You were number four.
I could set up
a software PBX for you.
Hell, I could set up 50.
( laughs )
Are you asking
for a job?
No, no.
I like my job.
I do.
It pays well,
the hours are good.
I work on games
in my spare time.
Okay, just because you
ripped off "Parallax"
does not make you
a game designer.
There's still
the actual concept,
the original invention.
You know, not just
sprinkling fairy dust on what
somebody else has created.
Since I don't want the job,
can I not have the lecture
as well?
Okay? Give me a call
if you want that PBX.
Okay.
I talked to three
different lawyers today.
They said the worst
thing we could do
is go confront
Rendon ourselves,
so I hope you didn't
do anything stupid.
He's hacking us
to get our attention.
And I think
he's the real deal.
( groans )
I can't believe
I'm saying this,
but I think
we should hire him.
He's interested.
He gave me his resume,
but I wanted to talk
to you first, so...
You already hired him,
didn't you?
Great.
I spent the entire afternoon
planning our legal strategy.
What an efficient use
of resources.
( sighs )
What did you
offer him?
$25,000.
Make it 20.
He'll take it.
I called the law office
where he works.
Once I told them
what he was up to,
they threw him under the bus.
His last two performance
reviews have been awful.
They were
gonna fire him anyway
and he knows it.
And if you
want to pay him more,
you can give him my salary.
Because if you keep making
unilateral decisions like this,
I will not be
sticking around, okay?
Yeah, okay.
And thank you.
( phone rings )
- Hello?
- Hey, how was your day?
( laughs )
Oh, no, no, no.
You first.
How was your day
at the office, honey?
Good, we're
computerizing records,
getting everything
archived.
And?
And, well, sometimes
I get to use
the microfiche machine.
Not to be sneezed at.
You, uh,
need approval.
All right,
this is my fault.
Oh, come on.
Of course it isn't.
Yeah, he's punishing you
for Peter.
What do you mean?
Peter--
he hooked my father,
got him deep
on a few deals.
One in Zurich
and this other thing.
But nothing ever materialized.
The deals weren't real.
All told, my father
lost a few million.
And this all happened
right before we got divorced.
My father
let his guard down
because of me,
and Peter never
paid him back a penny.
How come you never
told me that?
Because I--
I hate myself for it,
you know?
I-- I didn't want you
to see me as a victim
or an idiot.
But, you know, I'm gonna--
I'm calling my father
right now.
He has no right
to do this to you.
No, Sara, wait.
I've been stewing
about this all day.
I thought there
had to be some reason.
Well, now it's clear--
your dad is testing me.
He wants
to take my measure.
And after
what you just told me,
if you were my daughter,
I would do
the same thing.
Yeah, but it's stupid.
It's a waste.
You know, I'm not
gonna let you just--
I won't, don't worry.
I'm a big boy.
I'm learning a lot.
So we can just
let this breathe a sec.
Yeah?
Okay.
Uh, one more thing.
With what
I'm getting paid,
a two-bedroom in North Park's
not gonna happen.
( laughs )
I don't care.
I mean...
we could
pitch a tent.
I'll see you at home.
I love you.
Yeah, me, too.
Gordon:
Should I call 'em?
I'm really excited
for you guys to taste this.
( chuckles )
I saw
the takeout containers
in the trash, Gordon.
- Just testing.
- ( Donna laughs )
You like Sal's
cacciatore, right?
Hey, at least your obsession
with "Tank Battle" paid off.
My coder monkeys said
you came by, that your
time-stamp fix was genius.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I took a little break
from work, so...
Oh, sure, you did,
sexy beard.
Our log says you were online
for nine hours.
Hmm, well,
I must've left it on.
Anyways, the way
those nitwits coded it
made the problem even worse.
Did they show you
the delay?
Yeah, but that was
because of Tom,
this user
who hacked our system
who Cameron wound up hiring
after he ripped off "Parallax."
Sure, makes sense.
Good to know
she's still insane.
Well, apparently,
he had this breakthrough.
It's a software PBX
that allows up to 50 users
to play on
a single phone line.
- That would be huge.
- Yeah.
I'm tempted to go back
to that VC jerk
and see if it'll change
his mind, but I can't
bring myself.
How many potential users
are out there for Mutiny?
Now you sound like him.
Gordon, there's no way to know.
But isn't that critical?
I mean, it'll affect
your valuation
for the next round
of financing.
Yeah, but there's
no crystal ball.
Yeah, no, but, Donna,
maybe there is.
Look, you need a map
of the existing network.
Mutiny only sees a subset
at any given time,
but what if-- what if
anyone who could log on,
legitimately or not,
did it at the same time?
How many people
would that be?
- Gordon!
- Look, I gotta
get started on this.
- Eat without me!
- ( sighs )
You know, you can work here,
but you cannot live here.
( laughing )
Yeah.
Your letters
meant a lot to me.
The last one you sent,
you signed it Catherine.
Cameron was
my dad's name.
I started using it
after he died.
And I used to write letters
to him in Vietnam,
so I must've written that
by mistake.
Listen, Boz...
you can't just keep stuffing
envelopes around here.
I mean, our books
are a mess.
Accounts retrievable,
that whole thing--
Oh, come on, you know
it's "receivable."
No, no,
I don't know that.
Look, I suck at this.
We need you
to take a look at it,
work some CEO magic.
Plus we need help
raising money.
I mean, we'll get you
an office, we'll get
you your own corner--
Catherine.
I just need some time
to work some stuff out.
Get my head straight.
- Boz.
- Oh, come on,
as smart as you are,
I think I know myself
a little bit better
than you do.
My God, it's beautiful,
you lettin' me work here.
But I--
I'm just ready
for it, not yet.
How long do you need?
Honestly,
I don't know.
( elevator dings )
Mr. Wheeler,
this just came for you.
Was there a note?
Yes, sir.
It was stuck inside.
- Read it,
Caroline, will you?
- Of course.
It just says,
"Thank you for
the opportunity."
It's not signed.
I think it's
a waffle iron.
I know who it's from.
( keyboard clacking )
( music playing )