"Good Morning Judge" playing
♪ Well, good morning, Judge,
how are you today? ♪
♪ I'm in trouble,
please put me away ♪
♪ A pretty thing
took a shine to me ♪
- ♪ I couldn't stop her
so I let it be... ♪
- Nice.
♪ I couldn't stop her
so I let it be ♪
- ♪ I couldn't stop her... ♪
- Hey, code warrior.
♪ Couldn't stop her
so I let it be... ♪
- The girls are ready.
- ( music stops )
You fell asleep
on your transcripts.
Must've made
for some creepy dreams.
Hey, it's market research.
Uh-huh.
You know why your network's
on the fritz--
freeloaders.
Ghosts.
- We know how many
subscribers we have.
- Legit ones.
- Meanwhile, the cheats
gobble up your bandwidth.
- Uh-huh.
But what if someone
were to write a program
to find all your users
and map the actual size
of your network?
I call it Sonaris.
Listen to this:
"Your understanding of
U.S.-Soviet relations
is as shortsighted
as a lemur with cataracts."
They call it
a "flame war."
Donna, you realize
I'm doing this for you,
you know?
- Yeah, I know.
- Could you at--
And you must really
be enjoying it
because I haven't
seen you for two weeks.
Okay, well, will you
take a look, okay?
I'm almost done.
- But tell me something.
- What?
Who's your Superman?
- Oh.
- Mm.
- Huh, Lois?
- Oh.
- Lois Lane.
- Oh, Clark.
Wanna pretend
we're in a phone booth?
- Oh, God.
- Mm.
Just don't let Joanie
forget her juice.
Wait, I'll wear the cape!
Hey, glasses on.
You like it with the glasses.
( sighs )
Ow.
Puny earthling.
Hey.
- Is your car in the shop?
- Yep.
Nice wheels.
Does it have a horn?
Must've left it at home
with my clown nose.
( sighs )
Aw.
( laughs )
You got-- you got
her back.
Well, Ginnie
got the house,
Feds got
everything else.
Oh, but not this.
Whoo, God.
Can't thank you
enough, Barry.
- You and Louise...
- Glad to.
...holding on to this,
putting me up,
keeping the jackals
at bay.
And you put food on my table
for, what, 20 years?
Anything I can do
to repay you?
You can get in that tank
and drive it like a man.
( chuckles )
All right.
Barry:
There you go.
- ( engine starts )
- Yeah!
( both laughing )
Yeah.
- Eugene: Settling in?
- I am.
- Thanks, Eugene.
- Fine, that's just fine.
I've got some ideas,
though.
We double-check
all these documents
for scanning errors.
- Yes, sir.
- And sometimes I'll notice
a correlation
between a well's perforation
level and its drainage rate
and I'll make
a note of it here.
And if we all
took those notes,
we could harvest them
into spreadsheets,
- maybe find some--
- Data processing...
- Yeah?
- ...is on B1.
This is data entry.
That mainframe in there?
Our job is to fill it up.
Shovel sand,
not count the grains.
- And that
doesn't bother you?
- No.
Listen, I know staring
at 60 years of well depths
ain't exactly hair-raising.
That's why it helps
to have a pastime.
We're doing a decoy
decorating contest.
Drakes or hens,
your choice.
I myself... I collect
vintage percussion.
This weekend,
I was fortunate to obtain
a timbale favored
by the great Tito Puente.
Do you want
some coffee?
( computers humming )
( sighs )
( exhales )
( theme music playing )
Giant hands keep
reaching and grabbing
for your tasty
Jell-O chunks.
But you dodge them,
up, down,
shelf to shelf.
Soon the fridge is empty.
Only you, the Jell-O bowl,
have survived.
I call it "Jiggles."
( scattered applause )
Cool, uh,
questions, anyone?
- Uh, what flavor the Jell-O?
- Orange, obviously.
- "Jiggles" sounds
like a strip joint.
- Lev: Well, it's not.
Am I the only one
that's rooting
for the hands?
You know,
'cause the family's hungry
and you're available.
I feel like it's your job
to be eaten, you know?
Unless you're rancid,
moldy, like three weeks old.
Yeah, and then you
could call it, like,
"Jell-O Death Wish"
or something.
Your mission--
poison the family.
Kill 'em all.
- Totally.
- My Jell-O is not rancid.
Okay, let's just
let it breathe
for a second.
Thanks, Lev.
Uh, Tom.
Ideas?
Yeah, I'm working
on sprite scaling
for immersive
environments.
Okay, does it
have a story?
- Does it need one?
- Cameron: Uh, yeah, it helps.
Online gaming is different
from arcade or cartridge.
You're trying to draw
the players into a world,
- not just hustle
them for quarters--
- Tom: Are you joking?
Tons of titles have started
with tech breakthroughs.
"Xevious," "Zaxxon"--
Okay, let's just talk
about it in private, yeah?
Ah, spasibo.
- This something new?
- Yeah, "Parallax,"
chapter 22.
Hot off the presses,
so let's take a couple days
to play with it,
then we will debug
and load it onto
the network.
- Sound good?
- Yeah.
- All: Yes. Cool.
"The Rock Island Line"
playing
♪ He's already leaving,
but he won't be back ♪
♪ Well, the Rock Island Line,
she's a mighty good road ♪
♪ Rock Island Line,
it's the road to ride ♪
♪ Rock Island Line
is a mighty good road ♪
♪ Well, if you ride it,
you gotta ride it like you
find it ♪
♪ Get your ticket
at the station for the
Rock Island Line ♪
♪ Oh, I may be right
and I may be wrong ♪
♪ But you're gonna miss me
when I'm gone ♪
♪ Well, the engineer said
before he died ♪
♪ There are two more drinks
that he'd like to try ♪
♪ The doctor said,
"What could they be?" ♪
♪ A hot cup of coffee
and a cold glass of tea ♪
♪ Well, the Rock Island Line,
she's a mighty good road ♪
♪ Rock Island Line,
it's the road to ride ♪
it's a mighty good road ♪
♪ Well, if you ride it,
you gotta ride it like
you find it ♪
♪ Get your ticket
at the station for the Rock-- ♪
Bosworth:
♪ Get your ticket at the station
for the Rock Island Line ♪
♪ But if you wanna ride it,
gotta ride it like you find it ♪
♪ Get your ticket at the station
for the Rock Island Line. ♪
Whoo-hoo.
You're late.
Oh, what, I make all
your other boyfriends
hang fire?
( scoffs )
They can wait.
( chuckles )
( laughs )
( groans )
( phone ringing )
- Hello?
- Joe: Hey.
- You're early.
- My scanner can't tell
the difference
between lower case
Is and Ls.
Do you know what
every other word is?
- Oil.
- Sara: Oil?
( Sara laughs )
Me, I've spent the past hour
looking out the window.
At least you have one.
Was moving here
a mistake?
Uh, probably.
Oh, great.
I'm gonna go
pack tonight.
Sara, it was a joke.
We can't go back to Austin.
Your father would flip.
No, I-- I know,
I know.
And, look, I love my dad,
but screw him, you know?
Oh, God, I can't believe
I'm whining.
I hate when
I get like this.
Let's have dinner.
A dinner party
with other people.
Evan and Alicia
will drive up for
a free meal, right?
( laughs )
You could invite
your friends from Dallas.
Unless that makes you
uncomfortable.
No, that-- um,
that sounds like fun.
Let me get back to you.
Is that a personal call?
- Love you.
- ( dial tone )
Is Jacob Wheeler in?
Joe MacMillan.
Yes, I'd like to make
an appointment.
4:00? Absolutely,
that works for me.
I'll see you then.
Give people a dial-up,
they'll talk about anything--
politics,
sports, Kathy Ireland,
Billy Joel sucks--
Hey, Billy has chops.
I started a discussion
on Moog synthesizers.
It got 23 replies.
Can I borrow a coder?
We need to split Community
into multiple forums.
- It's exploding.
- Yes, okay.
Take Lev, please.
- Hey, how many online?
- 306.
- What?
- Yeah.
That's up, what,
50, week to week?
It's gonna be a bloodbath
in "Tank Battle."
Well, that's
the beautiful thing
about our business model.
Even the corpses
pay to play.
- That PBX patch is holding.
- So we're above water.
Well, we're just
not drowning so fast.
( moans )
I picked up
a new long-haul route.
- Oh, you did?
- Mm-hmm.
Where's the layover?
- Tokyo.
- Ah, me "wrikey."
- ( laughs )
- Tokyo.
( laughs, sighs )
It's gonna put
a serious hitch in these
little hanky-panks.
I'll just
stop by the house.
I wouldn't.
Well, what's
this about, then?
This...
is why I married you
in the first place.
The man in 25B.
Going dark on me?
It's okay.
Well, I paid
for that house.
And now it's mine.
And I can do what I want
with whom I want.
I understand that.
I just don't want to feel
that there's a broom
at my heels.
The world didn't stop
when you went to prison.
You ashamed of me,
Ginnie?
Not anymore.
All right, well,
I'll see you this
weekend, then.
I hope you're joking.
I just don't think
the time's right.
Well, hold on, now.
Is that why you
showed up today?
To convince me
not to go to Galveston?
Honestly, I didn't
think I'd have to.
We're not
your satellites anymore,
spinning around
the big man.
It was a fun ride
and a real hot show,
but this one's not yours.
Please don't come, John.
Promise you won't.
Let me know.
Love to Nancy
and the kids.
All right.
( sighs )
Some people don't
want to be saved.
Joe: You know
the most common last-second
regret of suicides?
People who jump off
bridges but live?
- High school girlfriends.
- ( chuckles ) Faucet left on.
Car running. Fridge open.
Just loose ends.
Okay, let me have it.
You're leaking data,
data that can be used
to increase yields,
predict profits, reduce risk.
I suggest folding
data collection and analytics
into a single department--
- Sure, do it.
- I'm not done.
I am.
Who's in charge
down there?
Uh, Eugene Bowdich.
Fire him.
Scrap the whole department.
Build your own.
It's the best way.
I'll let HR know.
I never thought you'd stay
on the basement level,
but if that's your goal...
I just need
a few days to prepare.
Take 'em.
Joe?
Seat opens up
on a crowded train.
It's okay to hesitate.
Maybe you're the next stop.
Maybe you're
a good Samaritan.
Or maybe you think
you don't deserve it.
Joe's voice:
So, that's it.
Thursday night, 8:00.
Hope you guys can make it.
Talk soon.
Okay, I just
need to listen to it
one more time.
- Mm-hmm.
- ( tape rewinding )
Joe's voice:
I'd love it if you
could come by
for a little dinner party
with me and my fiancée.
- Fiancée?
- Am I hallucinating?
Okay, you first.
Okay, I'm picturing
a perfume model.
- Dior--
no, no, no, Halston.
- Mm.
- Tall, blonde--
- Well, duh.
Daryl Hannah cheekbones,
shoulder pads,
Upper East Side.
No, no, no, no, no.
After Cameron, he'd want
a follower.
You know,
someone less challenging.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Worked for me.
- ( laughs sarcastically )
I'm going with a secretary,
Joan Baez type.
You know,
kittens on the futon.
- I guess we'll find out.
- ( laughs )
What, dinner?
With him?
Well, yeah.
Oh, come on.
Aren't you curious?
Mysteriously, my interest
in tall, dark mannequins
with delusions of grandeur
has dwindled,
but, hey,
knock yourself out.
Snob.
Sucker.
( tape rewinding )
Joe's voice:
Hey, Gordon and Donna.
It's Joe.
Joe MacMillan.
( tape rewinding )
That's it,
taste the pain.
Now, kneel.
Kneel before Zod.
( keyboard clacking )
Hey, babysitter's here.
Girls are building a fort.
Oh, you twisted
little mother.
- Excuse me?
- Yes, dear-- I mean,
yes, honey.
Damn it.
One of your freeloaders
just wasted me.
Okay, well,
I'm gonna go shower.
I want us accidentally
late on purpose.
Can't we bag?
I think I feel
a cold coming on.
Gordon,
this was your idea.
Well, how about
the two of us
just go out?
You know, Chaparral Club,
the Torch, you know?
We'll tell Rose to stay
the night, maybe rent
a room downtown.
I would love to.
That sounds great.
But we told them
we're coming.
Wheels up in 20.
"They can be
a great people, Kal-El;
they wish to be."
They only lack the program
to show them the way.
- ( keyboard clacks )
- ( modem squealing )
Sonaris.
Plays good for me.
- Me, too.
- ( rhythmic thudding )
Thanks.
I like the vampire
fish ladies.
Oh, yeah, the sea nymphs.
Uh, I ran out of land-based
creatures, so I--
Tom, did you
play the game?
Yeah.
And?
Let's talk about it
in private, okay?
Uh, no, we all
have a voice here.
What did you think?
Okay.
It took me
about an hour and a half.
- That's pretty fast.
- Because it's a rehash.
You stole the layout
from chapter nine
and the puzzles from 14,
you put them in a blender
- and hoped no one
would notice.
- No, I--
And of course if you get stuck,
the hairy lampshade
comes swooping in
and literally...
- What? It's a fez.
- ...drops clues on your head
like dandruff.
You know what I wanted to do?
I wanted to take that thing
by the pubes
and then fly outta there.
To some other game.
To someplace new.
This--
this shouldn't be updated,
it should be destroyed.
So stick that in your box.
( thumping resumes )
I...
- Donna: Ahem.
- ( knocks )
Oh, hey.
Wow, you guys
look great.
- Uh, here you go.
- Thanks.
It's-- I should've
clarified about--
Oh, come on.
I wear this every day.
Yay, finally.
I've heard a lot
about you guys.
I'm Sara.
Hey.
Joe, don't leave them
in the hall.
- Oh, sorry, come on in.
- Big galoot.
I love that word.
It comes from the Dutch.
It means either galley slave
or pirate or pimp.
But if I'm lucky,
all three, right?
- You guys want a drink?
- Donna: Oh, yes, please.
- Yeah, ahem.
- Um, gin and tonic,
hold the tonic.
( chatting, laughing )
Oh.
Ginnie:
I'm so proud of you,
I'm gonna cry.
( chatter continues )
Gordon:
So I told 'em,
"You got two choices.
Either pump the MSRP
or cover our tooling overages."
Of course, there were
no tooling overages.
You son of a bitch,
I taught you that move.
Yeah, create the sickness,
sell 'em the cure.
- It still works.
- Hell, yeah, it got me
a promotion this week.
- Gordon:
Mm, congratulations.
- So, this is cozy.
Yeah, we got
a bigger place in Austin.
This is just a pied-à-terre
for my auteur.
Yeah, I'm trying
to finish this article.
Well, actually,
I'm trying to start it.
- Oh, uh, about what?
- The Jarvik artificial heart.
- Oh, so, um,
nothing serious.
- ( laughs ) Well, yeah.
My friend
Alicia's doing the layout.
She's a professor of design.
Joe:
They should've been
here an hour ago.
Probably stuck
outside Waco
trying to fix a flat
tire with a metaphor.
- Gotta love academics.
- Lovely people, total flakes.
Joe, do you mind
helping me for a second?
Yeah.
- Who are you right now?
- What do you mean?
Don't you dare
apologize for my friends,
for our friends,
for this apartment,
or for me.
And if you're
done dick measuring
for the evening,
then you might
want to mention
the real reason
you got the promotion.
The truth.
Do you remember that?
And the apricots
are really good, too.
Little heavy
on the blue cheese, but--
All right,
where were we?
Mm, academia.
Right, you say that
like it's a nut you're
allergic to.
- ( Donna laughs )
- You know what, Sara?
I like you.
And I'm gonna give
you a really good
piece of advice.
Don't let him
hold out on you.
Come on, Joe.
What are you saving
all that Cardiff money for?
Hmm? Mutual funds?
Houseboat on Lake Travis?
I didn't get anything
from Cardiff.
Not a penny.
Pass the red?
"Conditioned" playing
♪ And I say nothing ♪
♪ Because I feel nothing ♪
♪ I've been conditioned
by your ignorance ♪
♪ To what you say and do ♪
♪ And you don't say
what you feel ♪
♪ You throw
feelings away ♪
♪ So I know nothing ♪
♪ And I feel nothing... ♪
We need you out here.
- Huh?
- Like right now.
- Damn it!
- It's a computer
game, okay?
Calm down.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Let me just check
the root file.
- ( speaks Russian )
- Bad software hit our network.
- It's overwriting our data.
- Our drives or the users'?
- Both.
- It just ate chess.
- What?
- Hey, we need to quarantine
all the unaffected machines.
- No!
- Anyone connected
right now...
- No!
- ...is vulnerable.
We have users online.
We're not-- we're staying up.
- It's starting on "Parallax."
- Christ, this thing is fast.
- There goes chapter two.
- Can somebody call Donna?
Yo-Yo:
We couldn't find her number.
- What?
- It's on a Post-it
somewhere.
Jesus.
I think that
it'll be fine.
Hi, can I speak to Donna?
What? Where?
It's Cameron.
Did she leave a number?
( groans )
Listen to me!
I need to speak
to Donna right away!
- ( laughs )
- ( phone ringing )
Hello?
( dial tone )
Shut it down.
The whole network?
Everything,
shut it all down.
Donna:
Maybe you changed him.
Sara:
No, he's nothing
like my ex.
Thought you were
strictly a beer guy.
I had this bottle
of "San-seer" at the mission
last summer.
It kind of rocked my world.
Sancerre.
Sans-who-gives-a-shit.
- Mm.
- Mm-hmm.
Mm, that's good.
It makes it all
worthwhile, right?
Oh, yeah.
She's burning
at both ends.
Every morning,
I peel her off the couch,
tuck her in.
My turn, I guess.
Anyhow, you traded up.
It's good to see you're
doing so well.
You, too.
Why didn't you tell me
you got screwed by Cardiff?
Well, I thought
I could live with it.
Well, I'd have gone
to him for you.
I mean, I wouldn't have
split my share or anything,
but, you know,
I would've spoken up.
I report every morning
to a basement.
( laughs )
I come home
to an apartment
that's smaller
than my old bathroom.
And yet if you offered me
this version of my life
or your payout,
whatever it was--
how much was it?
$838,100--
I'd choose this.
I'd choose her.
- Honey?
- Yeah?
Hey, I'm sorry.
Rose says Mutiny's
trying to reach me
and I called and their
phone lines are all tied up.
I think we should
head over there.
Oh, Donna,
is it serious?
No, it's probably
just a riot,
a massive fire,
or a Goobers overdose.
Joe, thank you
for a lovely evening.
Well, it was good
to see you.
Sorry we have
to cut it short.
It's okay.
Enjoy the Sancerre.
Gordon:
Sara, thanks
for having us.
Oh, my God,
I thought that
would never end.
What is he
doing with her?
And vice versa,
what do you think?
She's got some sort
of savior complex?
I don't know.
She seems impressive to me.
Yeah, well, I'm sure
her father's name opens
all kinds of doors.
Yeah, Joe's happy.
Minor miracle.
Yeah, of course he is.
He's got her completely
snowed.
Well, you look
lovely tonight.
Hey, uh,
thank you, Pop.
Now everyone
knows you're out here.
How are you, James?
Couldn't have picked up
a phone when you got out?
No, I wanted to
say this in person.
Oh, jeez,
here we go.
Look, the rehearsal
dinner's a damn milestone,
so sit back...
- close your piehole.
- ( chuckles )
"When his mother
and I found James on
the roof one Christmas,
waiting for Santa with
a flashlight and a long
list of questions,
we knew that
our boy wasn't afraid
of a challenge.
And now we know Lisa
isn't either."
- Ha-ha.
- ( snorts )
- "Pause for laughter."
- Oh, nice.
Okay.
"When James got his first
strikeout in Little League,
I was on a sales call.
When he graduated
from high school,
I was at a conference
in Tampa.
I know there are times
when it felt like his father
was nothing but a head rub
in the morning
and a shadow
in the door at night.
But not this night.
Not tonight."
May I see it?
I'd really like
to show Lisa.
( chuckles )
Look, I don't know
what Mom told you,
but I'm not angry at you.
I was, but I'm not.
I hear you got yourself
a hell of a gal, huh?
Aw, yeah.
Well, I'll have
you over to the--
over some night,
you know,
when I settle in.
Sure thing.
( inhales )
All righty, well,
wife's awaitin'.
( laughs )
It's gonna feel weird
saying that.
"My wife."
Well,
it gets easier.
Why don't you
come tomorrow?
( scoffs )
What, an ex-con
in the front pew?
Oh, your mother'd combust,
for God's sake.
( both laugh )
( imitates explosion )
Well,
Lisa wouldn't mind.
Neither would I.
Some other time.
All right.
- Take care of this old thing.
- ( taps roof )
( sighs )
Every disk
our subscribers load
will be infected.
We're gonna have to do
a clean reboot,
tell our users
to stay offline until--
We mail out new floppies?
Of everything.
Every game that we make.
And reimburse them
for ruining their
other software.
Chances are they've suffered
total data extinction
and they're gonna
blame us.
God knows
how many subscribers
we've lost for good.
( car door closes )
Oh, did you enjoy
your finger food
and cocktails?
Cameron, what is this?
What's going on?
A rogue program
ate our drives.
Nuked all our data.
- ( groans )
- Something called Sonaris.
Oh, shit.
You sent it?
I-- I mean, I--
before we left--
Stop.
You wrote this?
( men groaning )
No, uh, I didn't know
that he actually went
ahead and sent it.
You didn't know?
- You're married to him.
- What is that supposed--
We were trying to help
you map your network.
Look, let me in there,
maybe I can help.
- You want to help us?
- I'm sorry, all right?
You know, I'll buy you
some new drives.
Tom:
It's not the drives,
asshole.
We lost games.
We lost original work.
No, no, no.
He doesn't know
what that is.
You wouldn't
just stay away?
You couldn't just leave
us to do our thing?
Christ,
get over yourself.
I mean, which you hate
because it's new and brave
and because you're on
the outside looking in,
you sellout.
- Hey.
- Watch your mouth.
Meanwhile, your wife
is doing things
that you couldn't
even imagine.
- You want to
bring her into this?
- Okay. Gordon.
- Who signs your lease?
- Gordon!
Who pays your
water and electric
behind your back?
You know?
Donna's the whole reason
you haven't
been condemned!
Bet you didn't
know that, did you?
Or you or you or you,
Little Miss Girl Genius.
- You call this a company?
- Honey...
This is more like
"Nightmare on Nerd Street"!
- Hey, honey.
- What?
Would you go home?
- Donna.
- Just go home, please.
( chatting quietly )
Sir.
That's not your car.
( gasps, laughs )
( crickets chirping )
Ah.
( crashes )
( knocks )
We've got two XTs
up and running,
but games are still down,
Community, too.
We'll have to do a complete
reinstall from backups.
Do you want me
to apologize again?
This hurts me, too.
We're partners.
( Cameron scoffs )
Please.
This is your job, Donna,
but it's my life.
I live here, which means
I'm always gonna catch
the shit that has to be
dealt with right now
while you're at home
making popsicles
- and walking the dog...
- We don't have a dog.
...or letting an outside
party liquefy our business.
I'm here.
Why didn't you tell me
you were having dinner
with Joe MacMillan?
Well, I was pretty sure
you'd hold it against me.
Ding,
give the lady a prize.
- It was just dinner.
- Go home to your husband.
Oh, and, Donna.
If you ever put
another dime
of your own money
into Mutiny again
behind my back,
you're fired.
- You want a ride?
- No, thanks.
What can I do?
"Collapse" playing
♪ I'd sunk in oceans blue ♪
♪ Now they're
all frozen over ♪
♪ I should have
took your hand ♪
♪ We should have
crossed the border ♪
♪ Falling ♪
♪ On my own... ♪
( sniffling )
( breathing heavily )
( moaning, panting )
- Hey, uh, Cameron?
- Huh? Oh, just give
me a second.
( hyperventilating )
Whoa, whoa, hey.
Okay, Cameron,
just breathe, okay?
- I am breathing.
- Okay, hey. Hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey.
Breathe, Cameron, breathe.
Come here, come here.
Come here.
Come here. Sit down.
Just nod
or shake your head, okay?
Should I call a doctor?
Okay, are you
on any medication?
Squeeze, squeeze.
Harder, harder-- good.
- "Parallax."
- ( gasps )
Chapter three, level seven.
The cave of the four wizards.
- How do you-- focus.
- What?
How do you get the dragon's
egg across the chasm?
- What--
- 'Cause if you jump,
you're gonna drop it, right?
And there's a rope bridge.
But with the egg,
you're too heavy.
So, Cameron,
what do you do?
I don't know.
You go back.
That's right,
that's right.
You go back.
You turn around,
you go back inside,
and you face
the fourth wizard.
Right?
And then only by cracking
the egg in his chest
can you make him
human again.
( breathing slows )
Okay.
That's what I'm gonna
miss about "Parallax."
Those early chapters,
how every trap
had a reward,
every exit was
actually an entrance.
You know, the whole
thing made me feel like
"The Wizard of Oz."
But it was better
because you were
really like--
like inside the movie,
you know?
Running those balloons,
running through those
poppy fields?
It was like it was real.
I'm gonna let go, okay?
Yeah.
I'm gonna
get you some water.
Don't go anywhere, okay?
( sobbing )
How bad is it?
( yawns )
It's bad.
I should've
tested it more.
I just--
I got excited or...
I don't know.
I should have told you.
No.
No, I let it happen.
I didn't stop you.
What exactly
was the issue?
Oh, sorry.
( clanks )
Eugene:
Well, that's what I'm
trying to find out.
Uh-uh.
Yeah, hold on.
Hold on.
Morning.
( Eugene chuckles )
- Boy, that's funny. Yeah.
- ( sighs )
Meet me in
the mainframe room.
- I'm almost done.
- Now.
( door closes )
( exhales sharply )
( machines powering up )
( machines whirring )
( beeping )
These machines.
They work
the same shift as us.
Yep, 9:00 to 5:00.
- Why?
- Millions of dollars
of hardware
sitting unused
for 16 hours a day.
What's this about?
A way in.
- What?
- Never mind.
Back to work, then?
Yes, sir.
( theme music playing )