( whirring )
You know why vegetables
are a better way to start
your morning?
Because they contain fiber,
which helps with your digestion.
You know what that is?
I just did number two.
Can I have Frosted Flakes?
Remember our little talk
about trying new things?
98.7.
Get dressed for school.
Mommy, I still don't
feel well and Daddy's
making me go to school.
Sweetheart,
Mommy really can't afford
to get sick right now.
Let me make you
a pot of coffee.
Oh, thanks,
but I gotta get
to the office.
Could you feel my forehead?
I'm afraid I'm coming down
with whatever Joanie has.
Had.
Cool as a cucumber,
just like you.
( chuckles )
Come on,
you know I'm late.
All right,
I get it.
Gordon, I'm not mad.
I really am late.
No, I know.
I don't want you
to be late for work.
Uh, thank you
for squeezing me
into your schedule.
Happy to.
You've got my ear until
the day begins in earnest.
- What's on your mind?
- Opportunity.
Well, let me
stop you there.
I don't have
any job openings.
Well, that works out well
because I don't want a job.
You're sitting
on a gold mine.
Give me six months,
I'll turn Network
and Computer Systems
into an income-generating
department.
( laughs )
Okay, I'll play.
I work right next
to the mainframe sites.
They're powered on
all day, every day.
On nights and weekends,
they're just sitting there idle.
We lease
our mainframe space
and our network
during off hours
to third-party
businesses
who need a larger,
more powerful network.
Overhead is near zero.
It's pure profit.
It's too big
a security risk.
We have sensitive
business transactions
running on our mainframe.
Now, see,
you don't understand
how a mainframe works.
We can configure
the privilege settings
to lock these users into
a tightly controlled area.
Think of it
as a padded cell.
No outside user can access
our company files.
And that's
just the beginning.
This department
would be an incubator
for a large-scale operation.
We can turn
this juggernaut
into one massive,
forward-thinking entity
and you, you'll be
on a first-name basis
with Jacob Wheeler.
All we have to do
is imagine it, trust it,
and flip the switch.
If you believe so much
in this vision for Westgroup,
why don't you share it
with your future
father-in-law?
Oh, I know who you are.
You didn't think I'd take
a meeting with some plebe
from the data center, did you?
I was here before
her first marriage blew up
and I'll be here
after she's done
with you, too.
( sighs )
- You ready for this?
- Yeah.
- So do your thing
and then I'll--
- Yeah, I got it.
Okay, so, I just wanted
to thank everyone
for busting their asses
the last few days,
pretty much
without sleep.
It's no secret
that we're struggling,
through no fault
of anyone here,
to keep the lights on.
Every penny counts,
so thank you, guys,
for being such good sports.
It's not game over,
but we are on life support.
We're operating
with a third of our XTs
and our subscribers
keep cancelling.
( laughs )
I don't know, I guess
there's no honor among gamers.
So we're kind of--
look, we're spending more
than we're making,
which is
a mathematical--
We're almost out of money.
What little we have we need
to cover operating costs,
so what that means
is that we can't afford to pay
your salaries right now.
But in exchange for you
forgoing your salaries,
we're offering you
shares of the company,
which will be worth
a lot more in the long run.
- In success.
- Yes.
Yes, in success.
Look, this is what
we all signed up for.
It's the risk of working
at a company like this,
but don't forget
that the upside is
also so much greater.
I think it's a risk
worth taking,
but each of you
need to decide that
for yourself.
I'm in.
Me, too.
Yep.
( speaks Russian )
In.
( laughs )
I'm out.
C-come on, man.
It's been a sweet ride.
Student loans, sorry.
Hey, can we talk
about this?
I'm not going to take
that kind of risk
on a bunch
of online games.
( zips bag )
Have fun
writing cartridges.
That's what you've
always wanted to do,
so I just gave you
an easy excuse.
Or maybe I don't
think the shares
are gonna
be worth anything.
( theme music playing )
( paper rustling )
( sighs )
Two days in a row.
What, are you angling
to come back to work?
Work? You ain't paying
anybody anything.
More like volunteerin'.
No, I had an errand
to run this side of town.
Thought I'd bring you
over some breakfast tacos
'cause y'all are starting
to look like POWs around here.
Mm.
And I noticed this file
with your invoices in it
and a couple places where
you could cut some costs
popped out at me.
If you're interested
in hearing my suggestions.
Yeah.
That's it, I'm going
back to games.
Oh, no, Lev,
you're doing great.
You can handle this.
It's just six rooms.
18.
You really do
tune me out.
Come on,
how did that happen?
You told me any time
there's a lot of chatter
on a subject
to create a new room
for those users.
This is really
incredible, Lev.
I just finished creating
a new room and now a bunch
of bird feeder enthusiasts
have hijacked the Catty Cathys
to discuss using cat litter
- in the bottom
of bird feeders.
- Let me see, let me see.
So now the Catty Cathys
are pissed off
because they can't
follow their urine odor
removal thread,
which pisses me off
because I hate cats
and Chatty Cathys.
We have users
coming into our rooms
just to complain?
Do we have people signing up
just for Community?
Do you need me
to draw you a Venn diagram
of cat ladies and gamers?
Not a whole lot
of overlap.
Now can we please
ask Cameron for another body?
When we get up to 30 rooms,
you let me know.
We already
sent out mailers
with instructions on
reinstalling the software.
- They're still cancelling.
- Well, of course they are.
You just gave
your girlfriend
the clap.
You think
sendin' out mailers
is gonna fix that?
- ( laughs )
- You gotta send her flowers,
not penicillin.
- What do you suggest we do?
- First of all, your image
needs rehabilitation.
I noticed an invoice here
for prepaid ad space
in "Byte Magazine."
Look, use this
to change the story.
That sounds great,
but we can't afford
an ad agency right now.
No, you don't need one.
Two words in bold black
lettering-- we're hiring.
Folks see that,
they think you're cooking
on the front burner.
Look, and a little splash
of color would be nice
in there somewhere.
Draw the eye,
won't break the bank.
Yeah, maybe a photo
of our staff at work.
- Bosworth: Mm-hmm.
- ( laughs ) Yeah,
that'll really pop.
What, Bodie and Wonderboy
hunched over their keyboards?
Yeah, or it'll remind people
of Steve Jobs starting Apple
in his garage.
People can't
seem to get enough
of that old chestnut.
Hey, no more cold calls.
You've got to go door-to-door.
- Boz, we don't
have the manpower.
- Just go after the whales.
- Hmm?
- Your whales,
your top dogs.
Those 10 names
that I highlighted here,
these are
your biggest spenders.
Start with them.
Uh, okay, I guess
we could send Lev out.
He k-kind of passes
for normal.
Oh, no, no,
I need Lev for Community.
- Why?
- We're up to
almost 20 rooms.
- What? That's huge.
- I know, that's a little bit
of good news, right?
- W-when did that happen?
- Ahem.
- Just this morning.
He showed me--
- Ahem!
Ladies, this is
where you say,
"Could you please do this
for us, Bosworth?
You are an unbelievable
salesman."
And I say,
"No, that chapter
in my life is closed."
And then you say,
"Please do us this favor?"
And I say,
"No, I cannot."
And then it goes
back and forth like that
a couple more times
and I say yes.
Thanks.
I can take it from here.
What am I supposed to write
on the work order?
What work order?
What's going on?
Why am I the only one
pitching today, guys?
Come on, sky's the limit.
Whatever-- whatever
comes to mind.
Come on, guys,
let's get serious.
There's shares
on the line here.
- ( laughs )
- Oh...
Yeah.
Uh, we could do
our version of "Bard's Tale,"
but the players try to free
a princess who's actually
a hobbit in disguise.
( men murmur )
Okay, I think
we need to go bigger.
Uh, maybe I'm not
explaining it very well.
You see,
the players, um--
What if we create
a shooter game
that's totally
immersive?
That shows the player's
perspective of his surroundings.
- And you want to try
to do this online?
- Yeah. What?
I mean, I know we're
more limited in the kind
of graphics we can do,
but if we pulled it off,
it would be amazing.
Uh, what's a good enemy?
And no tanks or aliens.
- We need something fresh.
- ( door closes )
- Morning.
- Sorry, I got held up.
- Okay, leave
a little earlier.
- ( men snicker )
- Bodie: Okay,
I-- I got it.
- Yeah.
Find and kill E.T. before
he eats your Reese's Pieces.
- No!
- ( men laugh )
Amit:
Bodie, that's,
like, the worst.
Okay, let's stop
while we're stuck
and then we can
pick up again tomorrow.
- Good?
- Well, that was...
Arki:
Bodie, it was a bad idea.
He will eat candy.
You cannot kill E.T.
Bodie:
It's just
some Reese's Pieces.
- Hey.
Sorry, would you be
more comfortable in one
of the bedrooms?
No, no, I'm good.
I just need to fuel up.
- What's going on
with you?
- Nothing.
I just-- I slept
through my alarm
and I guess
I'm just really tired.
Okay, we're all
really tired.
Just because you're not
getting paid anymore
doesn't mean you can
show up late for work.
- It's bad for morale.
- It won't happen again.
- Okay.
- ( panting )
- ( birds chirping )
( distant dog barking )
Hey.
I didn't see you there.
- You been waiting long?
- Just got here.
Oh, I was out
doing my miles.
Did-- did nine miles.
Whoo!
( panting )
You want a smoothie?
I'm making one for myself.
Sure. When did you start
drinking smoothies?
Um...
- hold on, let me get closer.
- ( button clicking )
I wasn't kidding there
when I told you I was
getting back into shape.
You know,
1985's my year, man.
I'm eating better,
I'm exercising.
You know, I haven't jogged
regularly since, I mean,
I don't even know.
Adidas came out
with that track suit.
Exactly.
It's already
paying off, too.
Doctor called yesterday,
said that my blood work's good.
Said I've got the body
of a 25-year-old.
Hmm.
All right.
- ( blender whirring )
- Ah.
I programmed the remote
to turn on all the electrical
appliances in the house.
- Pretty innovative, huh?
- You know, I've been doing
some innovative stuff
at Westgroup Energy.
Oil's taking a big hit
and the industry needs
to diversify, so...
- ( whirring continues )
- Hmm.
- ( whirring stops )
- Joe: It's a perfect moment
to take Westgroup
into the Information Age.
Um, have you heard
about time-sharing?
Yeah, I've heard
of time-sharing.
Westgroup's got
a brand-spankin'-new
IBM 3090 mainframe
still in beta
at headquarters
downtown.
I'm starting there
and then moving to the 3081
in London and New York.
Wow, shit.
Profit margins
will be huge.
Yeah, it'll make ARPANET
look like two tin cans
and a fishing line.
So I'm looking for
a ground-floor engineer
to convert the mainframes
for outside dial-in access.
Wait, you're not trying
to sell me on this, are you?
No, we're just talking.
You're reading too much
into it.
I'm looking for someone.
You're the best engineer
I know.
I wanted to give you
the first right of refusal.
- Be flattered.
- I am flattered, all right?
And I refuse.
- I thought
we were getting along.
- We are getting along.
Let's not ruin it
by jumping back into
business together.
Come on,
it's one day's work.
They're still running
Cardiff Systems software.
You could do it
with your eyes closed.
When you invited me and Donna
to dinner last week,
was that to butter me up
for this?
I didn't even have this idea
when I invited you to dinner.
Is Sara even your fiancée,
or is that just some person
that you hired
- to make yourself seem
normal and trustworthy?
- Now you just sound crazy.
No, crazy is doing
the same thing over
and over again
and expecting
a different result.
You do understand this area
of tech is exploding, right?
In 18 months,
we'll be bigger than
CompuServe by a power of five.
Where will you be
in 18 months?
I don't know.
Maybe drinking mai tais
poolside in Maui
off all the money
I made on the Giant.
I'm sorry, Joe.
You're gonna have
to find somebody else.
( knocks )
- Oh, hey there, son.
Is your daddy home?
- No.
- When do you expect him?
- Well, that's the
million-dollar question.
Look, whatever
you're selling,
I'm not interested.
Ma'am, I'm not
selling anything.
My name's John Bosworth,
by the way.
I'm head of Customer
Satisfaction at a company
called Mutiny.
I just came by this morning
to apologize to your son here
about all our
network hassles this week
and see what I can do
to bring him back into
the Mutiny family.
Nothing.
I'm the one that cancelled
the subscription, okay?
He's been racking up
hundreds of dollars
on my credit card.
Can't remember the last time
that he had a friend home
from school.
I mean...
( scoffs )
You video game companies
are no better than
drug peddlers.
Oh, I'm sorry, ma'am.
I didn't realize our services
had disrupted
your boy's social life.
- What grade
are you in, son?
- Ninth.
Yeah, your mama's right.
You gotta spend more time
with your buddies at school.
All they talk about
is sports.
Well, that's not true.
What about Gavin?
Have any of these Mutiny users
become friends of yours?
Oh, yeah, like 32.
Well, that I talk to
regularly.
Maybe six or seven
that just want to
play against me,
- which is also fun.
- ( scoffs )
I don't understand
how you're talking
to all these people.
I never hear
a peep out of you
when you're down there.
( sighs )
My mother's a Luddite.
We type messages
to each other.
That's how you
talk online.
Ma'am, you and I
are too old school
to understand this,
but to your son here
and his friends,
Mutiny is the church.
It's where
they find community.
Sometimes that's
the only place.
( Bosworth chuckles )
You have a good day.
I'm sorry to have taken up
so much of your time.
Wait, um,
what'd you say
your name was again?
It's John.
John Bosworth.
- ( knocks )
- Hmm?
I heard you were
looking for me?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um, okay, so I've been
doing some inventory,
trying to figure out
what games we can
afford to lose
to help lighten the network.
That's smart.
Did you want
suggestions or...
Well, I was thinking
that Backgammon and Checkers
are no-brainers.
They're our lowest performers
and not one of our originals.
Yeah, that's great.
And I'm gonna have
to cut Community.
- Huh? Why?
- Well--
The only bandwidth it takes up
is people on it typing,
and no one types
as fast as even the slowest
telephone modem.
It's not about bandwidth.
It's about security.
Community's our
most vulnerable spot.
Someone shares
the wrong file,
we get infected again.
I just--
I can't take a chance
on that happening.
If you want
to make this a place
where people can connect,
then there's going
to be risk involved.
I know.
I'm just not willing to take
a risk on something so small.
We've tripled in a week.
A lot of our users
aren't even gamers
and it requires
very little manpower,
so I have to be
honest with you,
I think this
is a huge mistake
from a business
standpoint.
Noted.
( chatter, laughter )
- ( gasps )
- Oh, sorry.
( snickers )
- Give me that.
- I'm sor-- sorry.
Sorry, sorry!
Uncle!
Jesus!
God, you scared
the shit out of me.
What are you do--
how long have you
been in here?
Since you and the girls
got home.
It's the only place
they don't look for me.
( voice breaks )
I've had a day.
Okay, well,
I know that feeling.
I had weeks like that.
What happened?
Cameron's cutting
all of my Community rooms
just when they're taking off.
And she was so polite
about it, too.
All business.
It was unbearable.
Well, you're always saying
how you wished she'd be
more professional.
Yeah, but not
against me.
( scoffs )
We're supposed
to be partners.
Why don't you get undressed
and take an actual bath, okay?
I'll put the girls to bed
and I'll order takeout for you
- from whatever
restaurant you want.
- No, I'm not hungry.
Do you remember
how you felt the first time
you powered on the Giant
- and you knew it was
something special?
- Yeah.
Well, I felt the same way
when the first user entered
my Community room.
It was like--
I don't know,
it was like giving birth.
You know?
I know that sounds crazy.
Look, it doesn't
sound crazy at all.
Look, you created it.
It is your baby.
Yeah.
( voice breaks )
It's really nice
that you get it.
I don't know.
I don't know if I'm
cut out for this.
Hey, look,
you can do this, okay?
You're too lost to see it,
but I can see it.
Forget what Cameron thinks.
This is a big idea.
You have to see it
through.
But what's the point?
Even if--
even if we get
all the XTs back
up and running,
we can't survive
long-term on a rickety,
homemade network.
Look, you'll-- you'll
figure something out.
Would I be a terrible mother
if I stayed in here until
the girls went to sleep?
Yes.
- Hey.
You're--
you're out late.
Or early, depending
on your sleep schedule.
Uh, yeah, I couldn't get
any work done during the day
with the phones ringing,
so I-- I'm just here
to get snacks.
- Right, yeah...
- Grocery store, so...
- I didn't know you worked here.
- I'm actually here undercover.
Um, for our games.
I'm doing some research.
I got one already.
"Stock Boy."
It's where the players
have 10 minutes to try
and stock all the shelves
while dodging senior citizens
on the hunt for adult diapers.
- ( laughs )
- I used to work here
in high school
and the manager let me
pick up a couple shifts.
- Yeah, of course, it's--
- It's just till the shares
are worth something.
That's great.
I-- I mean,
it's not, like, great.
Yeah, the FireBall
Jawbreakers,
they're at the bottom shelf
at the end of aisle six,
and the Good &amp; Plentys are
halfway down the same aisle,
but they're on the right.
It's hard to miss.
You always leave a trail
of wrappers in your wake.
( car engine starts )
Cool.
Uh... right.
( laughs )
I'll see you in a few.
- Yep.
- Okay.
Here are my terms.
First off, I'm in charge.
Second, I'll provide
my services for free
in exchange for Mutiny being
your first client, all right?
And third, dude,
this is a pilot program.
I expect a discounted rate.
So, what did you screw up
over at Mutiny?
Nothing. I'm just trying
to help out my wife.
All right, let me
get this straight.
Donna asked you
if Cameron's company
could be
my pilot program.
They're desperate.
They're not desperate.
Look, the company's
in great shape.
Do we have a deal or not?
All right, I put together
an equipment list.
Just so you know,
converting the mainframes
for time-sharing
isn't as easy
as just flipping a switch.
I mean, the T-1
connections alone
are gonna take a few days.
I already had three
T-1 high-speed lines
installed.
I just need you
to finish the connections
and install IBM's
time-sharing option.
All right.
Well, we should use
Michigan Terminal Systems.
You know, it's much more
reliable than IBM.
Could you do it tonight?
- Why tonight?
- Can you do it
or can't you, Gordon?
Yeah, yeah,
I could do it.
Great, why don't
you grab this stuff
and meet me at the bar
across the street at 8:00?
Why don't you grab this stuff
and meet me at the bar at 8:00?
Okay, um, before I go
screw myself,
when was the last time
that you got the head of
CompuServe on the phone?
Also, we're not
CompuServe!
- ( knock on door )
- Yeah?
- This a bad time?
- Huh? No, no, come in.
Just doing
some customer service.
Can I ask you a question?
Have you ever used
Mutiny Community?
Yeah.
- What's your question?
- That. That was my question.
I just thought
you should try it before
you decide to drop it.
But you have,
so I'll leave it to you.
Okay.
What's your favorite room?
- What?
- Your favorite room.
All the guys have one.
I'm just curious.
I know what Community is.
With respect,
I disagree.
It's simple text
with no graphical capability
or playability.
- Oh.
- Am I wrong?
The code might not be
revolutionary,
but the interactions between
users are a completely new way
of communicating.
People can be more authentic
online than in real life,
and that is addictive.
Okay, fine.
I'll give a spin
in Community.
Just don't expect me
to change my mind.
Because you just
don't like it
or because it didn't
come from you?
"Things Can Only Get Better"
playing
( song continues playing
in background )
( cheering, clapping )
Whoo!
Can we turn the heat
back on now?
Aw, come on.
Get yourself a new
wool skirt, milady.
- ( laughing )
- We just got back
another subscriber.
I think we
should celebrate.
Cameron bought those
for tonight.
Oh, right, we're still
on the clock.
Or are we?
- ( laughter )
- Bodie: Heads up.
( all cheering )
( all chanting )
Drink! Drink! Drink!
You're spilling on my shares.
How am I gonna feed myself?
( computer beeps )
Wonderboy:
God, man.
( laughing, cheering )
♪ But I won't stop
and falter ♪
- ♪ And if we
throw it all away... ♪
- ( keyboard clacking )
♪ Things can only
get better ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
- ♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa... ♪
- ( keyboard clacking )
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa ♪
♪ Treating today
as though it was ♪
♪ The last,
the final show ♪
♪ Get to 60
and feel no regret ♪
♪ It may take
a little time ♪
♪ A lonely path,
an uphill climb ♪
♪ Success or failure
will not alter it ♪
♪ And do you feel scared?
I do ♪
♪ And I won't
stop and falter ♪
♪ And if we throw it
all away ♪
♪ Things can only
get better ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa... ♪
Um, that went to everyone.
- What do you--
- Everyone.
I know this isn't
the best time to tell you this,
but for future reference,
the letter D plus the shift key
plus exclamation mark
means "direct to all."
( gasps )
( keyboard clacking )
( music playing
in background )
- All right, I got
everything in my trunk.
- Hey.
I didn't have time
to tape them all
to one sheet,
so fill out
the expense report
for me, will ya?
- Mm.
- Hey, any chance you guys
carry Anchor Steam?
- Mm-mm.
- Well, uh, give me
whatever's that's on tap.
That's all I got on me.
I'll give you the rest
by the end of the week.
Why are you reimbursing me
with your own money?
Did you get me
that security badge?
You don't need
a security badge.
- Why not?
- It's after hours.
Isn't that all the more reason
I need a security badge?
( cash register dings )
- Joe?
- Hmm?
I tried to do this
all by the book,
but I was getting stonewalled
by some half-wit lifer
- who couldn't even understand
the concept of passive income.
- Oh, unbelievable.
Look, I don't think
you understand the concept
of good faith.
I knew if I told you
I was doing this on the side,
- you'd make
a big deal about it.
- Oh, "on the side."
No, it is a big deal.
Why didn't you take this
to your future father-in-law?
- Okay? It's a great idea.
- He wouldn't get my vision
the way you did.
It would just be words.
I needed evidence
to back it up so he
could trust me.
And what better way
to earn his trust
than to break into his building
in the middle of the night
and mess with his
state-of-the-art mainframe?
- It's a better play.
- Oh, it's a better play.
- Does Sara know about this?
- She's in Austin
for the night.
Mm, all right, well,
let's call her up, tell her
what we're about to do,
and if she's okay with it,
then I'm happy to help.
Okay, after we
call up Donna
and tell her that
she'll be leasing her
new network from me.
Listen, Donna and I,
we don't hide anything
from each other.
Great, let's call her up.
I'd love to say hi.
You know,
I'd like to punch you
in the face right now.
Be my guest.
Okay, I lied.
I don't know how
to use Community.
How is anybody
supposed to respect me
when you're
disrespecting me?
- Did you think
about that?
- No.
Did you think about that
at all when you were
messaging with Tom?
No, I-I-- honestly,
I wasn't thinking at all.
- Yeah.
- Do you want me to go
apologize to everyone?
No, don't do that.
Don't do anything.
Donna, haven't you ever
said something shitty
about somebody in private
that you'd never say in public?
- That you don't really mean?
- That's not what we're
talking about.
If you have a problem
with Gordon, you come to me.
You don't talk about it
behind my back
and you don't ever--
don't ever talk about
my kids.
- Whoa, are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Do you want water?
- No, I'm fine.
I just think
on top of everything else
I have Joanie's flu.
( sighs )
I'm really sorry.
You know that feeling
of freedom that you had
when you're sending
private messages with Tom?
That feeling that you
had a place to go
where you could say things
you wouldn't say in person?
That--
that is the value
of Community.
I need you in there.
We're doing
the group photo
for the "Byte" ad.
I'm doing a take
on class photos
from high school,
and without
you two, it looks like
the abstinence club of 1985.
Okay.
( distant dog barking )
( sighs )
Okay, guys.
Guys, guys, can we
put down the beer
for, like-- just, like,
five minutes?
Five minutes, okay?
Okay, you're gonna
come right here.
Right here.
Put it down over there.
Come here, come here.
Get in line.
Wonderboy, right here.
Okay, here we go.
- Nice and--
- Whoa.
Sorry.
Stand there in the line.
Take a look at this.
Okay. Wait, where's--
where's Bodie, guys?
Eh, he's in the bathroom, Tom.
He's in the bathroom?
Well, can someone go get him?
Please?
Jesus, guys, I feel like
I'm running a nursery here.
Okay, tighten up, guys.
Put down the beer.
Okay, here we--
no, no, no, no, no.
Here, you gotta come
front and center.
Donna, front and center.
Okay?
Okay? Right here.
That's great. Thank you.
Okay, this is
looking good, guys.
Okay, on three.
Big smiles.
One, two, three.
Donna, Cameron,
that is perfect.
Do you mind lifting
the corners of your mouths?
Like a whole lot?
Okay? Here we go.
Okay, on three.
Lev, Lev, you're
blocking Wonderboy.
- Okay?
- I can't hear
without my glasses.
You can't hear
without your glasses.
- Jesus!
- Whoa!
I just bought this shirt!
Okay, guys.
Wonderboy! Wonderboy!
Wonderboy,
just stop, okay?
Everybody just stop.
Can we just get together?
Just for, like,
one minute?!
Good, great.
Big smiles, all right?
Jesus.
One, two--
- Whoo-hoo!
- ( all laughing )
- That's great.
That's great. Thanks.
- Did it look good?
- Complete disaster.
That's good.
- Oui, oui!
- Give me that beer.
Give me that beer.
- Whoo!
( music playing
in background )
Watch out!
Ah! Get down!
- Ah!
- Ah! Watch it!
( darts firing )
( shouting )
Wonderboy:
Watch out,
he's on red team!
Amit:
Get him! He's over there.
- Hey, Carl?
- Uh, yeah?
Did you take down
Community yet?
Oh, um, no,
but I promise I'll do it
before I leave tonight.
And I'm pretty sober, so...
No, it's...
just leave it up
for a few more days, okay?
Okay, great, that's good
'cause I'm not at all sober,
so...
- Thanks. See ya.
- Bodie: Man comin' in.
Coming in!
Cover me!
Get your head in the game.
15 seconds.
Red team.
You got 15 seconds
before I shoot you.
Look out, look out!
"Don't Wanna Lose"
playing
- ( dart gun cocks )
- ♪ If you listen close,
you might hear the sound ♪
♪ Well, I would never
let you down ♪
- ♪ I thought you were
a man of action... ♪
- ( groans )
( screams )
♪ Well, come on,
baby, come on, give me
a little reaction... ♪
- ( both scream )
- Okay, go.
- Okay, got it.
- ( shouts )
Careful, behind the desk.
Behind the desk!
Get him! Get him!
- ( darts shoot )
- ( groans )
Get down.
( all shouting )
- Hallway's clear.
- Oh, God!
- They shot me!
He got me.
- No!
- ( dart gun clicks )
- ( chuckles )
- Out of ammo.
- You're dead.
- ( dart shoots )
- ( groans )
- ( laughs )
- Got him!
- Got your guns, babe.
- Ammo.
- Here, take his gun.
- Bodie: Lord, help me.
- ( groans )
- Oh, sorry.
Bodie:
Cameron, watch out!
Take cover!
( screaming )
- I'm hit!
- No!
- Ah!
- ( both laughing )
Oh, you wanna
shoot me so bad.
Why? Because you stopped
paying us, but you're still
riding all our asses?
- Yeah, something
along those lines.
- And you're imperious
and you're stubborn
and you never, ever give
constructive criticism.
I get it,
I'm a horrible boss.
Actually, I like
all that about you.
So... why haven't you
taken a shot at me yet?
I don't know.
'Cause I sure
as hell want to,
but I also kind of
want you in the game.
Yeah?
- That's it.
- What's it?
This.
We create
this game online.
- We can't compete
with box games, right?
- Yeah.
But what we have going for us
is we're networked.
Instead of shooting
at a tank or a robot,
what if you're shooting
at another user
on our network?
I mean, human players
aren't predictable
like a computer-generated
enemy.
I mean, how cool
would it be
if you're looking
right at them, eye to eye?
- Your friend
is also your enemy.
- Yeah.
I mean, who doesn't want
to shoot their friend
sometimes?
But how would
we do the graphics
over the network?
We'd have to do--
build half of it on the C64
- and then the other half
on our network.
- Yes.
And the C64,
that can manage
the scenery graphics
and the player movement,
and we can manage
the user's location,
whether or not they can--
they can see each other,
the score,
all that sort of thing.
And we'd have to
build a protocol between
the user's computer and ours
- so that we can
control the game graphics.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course.
As long as they're short,
encoded instructions.
Yeah, to keep
the game speed up and--
- ( both scream )
- ( phone ringing )
Jesus!
I'm on your team, asshole.
Excuse me, we're trying
to work in here.
( both laugh )
- Amit: Hey, where's Rendon?
- Bodie: He's dead. I shot him.
Amit:
Well, go back and tell him
that his date's on the phone.
Bodie:
Yo, Tom, a lady's
on the phone.
- ( laughs )
- Uh, I gotta go.
Okay, have fun.
( coders chattering )
You're such
a gentleman.
Wonderboy:
He went back that way!
Get him!
( shouting, laughter )
( glasses clatter )
People are gonna
be here in two hours.
Yeah, well...
How much longer?
You sound like my girls
on a road trip.
You're slower
than you used to be.
Well, you want me
to slap this thing together
like the Giant Pro?
I'm almost done slotting.
Then I gotta upload
the hosting
and time-sharing options
that'll switch the TSO--
That's not on you,
the Giant Pro.
No one machine
can be everything
to every customer.
We're all guessing in the dark
to a certain extent.
Yeah, well, I have no idea
what consumers want
and I'm sick and tired
of trying to figure it out.
You know, I wish--
I wish people would just
tell me exactly what they want
and then I would
go and build it.
Like a tailor
making a custom suit.
Exactly.
I can build anything.
Let me grab you
a fresh Coke.
( door opens, closes )
Hey, hey,
what happened?
Oh, nothing.
I just, uh--
I just fell.
I must've tripped.
- On what?
- I caught my foot on the edge
of the cabinet here.
Look, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Let's just keep going.
Look, the sun's almost up.
Hey, Gordon,
you don't look so good.
What are you,
my mother?
Thanks for the soda.
- ( door opens )
- ( footsteps )
( claps )
- Bosworth: Oh.
- Well, you're here early.
Yeah, this one fella
was never at home.
Only way to catch him
was in his car,
in the garage,
as he pulled out
on his way to work.
( chuckles )
- Here.
- You know...
All right.
I'm not gonna ask you
to work here again, okay?
I'm telling you.
You start tomorrow.
This is your office.
It has an open-door policy,
obviously,
because it is the kitchen.
- ( imitates explosion )
- Your first task...
is I need you to help me
run this company better.
Yes, ma'am.
I mean it.
I want to be
better at this.
( sighs )
When I was 23,
my job at Cardiff
was to do one thing--
put the hand radio kits
in the box for shipment.
That's it.
Wasn't even responsible
for labeling them.
( laughs )
I just boxed 'em,
punched out, and drank beer.
- ( laughs )
- ( sighs )
- ( chuckles )
- ( door opens )
You'll get there.
- ( door closes )
- When?
Hey.
I got the film developed
from the-- yeah.
I don't know-- I don't know
if there's anything...
like, usable in there.
Hey.
( scoffing )
We've howdied,
but we ain't shook.
- John Bosworth.
- Tom Rendon.
( laughs )
Oh, my God.
( laughing )
And there's your ad
right there.
Yeah.
"Play with friends."
That's the tag.
Mm.
You're
in a good mood.
Your date
must have gone well.
Uh, it was terrible,
actually.
I had to cut it short.
Aw, she wouldn't put out?
Funny.
So funny.
No, I, uh--
well, I couldn't stop
thinking about the game.
( groans )
I know, me, too.
( laughs )
I'm sorry.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Donna, how much longer
you gonna be in there?
Donna:
I don't know.
Mm.
You know, maybe you should
go see a doctor, you know?
Just to rule out
anything serious.
No, I think I--
I must've just got
what Joanie had.
Well, I got
some great news
that I think'll make you
feel better.
You know that consulting gig
I did last night?
Well, I convinced, uh,
my contact over there
to lease their network
to Mutiny for $3 an hour.
Okay, nobody's getting
that kind of deal.
You'll be able to run
thousands of Community rooms.
How's that
for turning lemons
into lemonade?
Donna, did you hear me?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Um, that is amazing news.
Are you throwing up?
Hmm?
Yeah.
Can you give me a sec?
Yeah, sure.
I'll be in the kitchen.
( sighs )
( music playing )