( both exhale )
I finally
thought of something
I like more about
Dallas than Austin.
You're in Dallas.
( button clicks )
- ( coffee brewing )
- Son of a bitch.
Joe: Sara?
Everything all right?
( Sara dials phone )
Caroline,
it's Sara.
Put my dad on the phone.
Got your little present
in the mail.
The one from your lawyers.
Even if I wanted to,
this is how you do it?
You don't even
ask me about it?
No, this isn't
up for debate.
Yeah, no kidding, Dad.
You know, I was the one
who went through it.
So when are you gonna stop
treating me like this?
I'm not a kid.
Just stop.
Stop now.
Because I trust him
and I want him to know that.
He deserves better.
I'm not gonna do that to him.
Cameron:
I know, the network's fast,
but we don't have anything
that maximizes it.
We have this... racecar
and it's just idling.
Well, we have a race track.
What we need is a racecar.
You're really annoying.
But this will be
our racecar.
Two player,
first person game,
online,
over dial-up.
We still have to figure out
what it's about.
What it's about.
Yeah, we will.
Between the two of us.
And our crack team.
( laughs )
( Russian accent )
It will be excellent game,
like steal the bread
from the weak little boy.
It is good
impersonation I do.
( Russian accent )
If you were impersonating
the cyborg sent
to kill Sarah Connor.
( normal voice )
Oh, damn, that came out today.
- ( normal voice ) Oh, yeah.
- Yeah, I want to go pick it up.
My friend at Suncoast
was gonna reserve a copy.
What time is it?
I gotta go.
( groans )
If I'm late,
my boss is gonna
have my ass.
Oh, she sounds like
such a bitch.
Oh, you have no idea.
( German accent )
Your clothes, give them
to me now.
- ( laughs )
- Stop with the impressions.
You, me, "Terminator,"
tonight.
( normal voice )
Okay.
Oh!
Hey.
- Mornin', sunshine.
- Ha.
You just headin' home?
Uh, just for a couple hours.
( laughs )
Attagirl.
Now get some shut-eye.
I'll make sure the place
doesn't burn down without you.
- All right.
- ( slaps car )
Hey, good morning.
Long night?
You want some coffee?
I kind of want a beer.
Is that bad?
Hell, no.
A long day at work,
I'd have two.
- Where are the girls?
- They're brushing their teeth.
( beer can hisses )
Oh, that is too good.
Everything going
okay over there?
Yeah, it's amazing.
You know, Community's
expanding so fast.
It's just a lot of work,
but it's work I want
to be doing.
- Mmm.
- Oh, shoot.
You know, we need to get
in touch with somebody over
at what's it called.
They haven't sent us
our first invoice and we
need to figure out billing.
Oh, well, I'm sure
they'll probably send
something over, you know?
Yeah, I just want to make sure
we get this deal in writing.
It seems almost
too good to be true.
Right, well,
I'll talk to him.
You know, you've got
enough on your plate.
You know, stuff you
actually want to be doing.
- Yeah--
- Oh, I wanted to talk
to you about this.
I've been thinking
about doing something
with this made-to-order
computer business.
Yeah, you should.
( spits )
Something wrong?
No, no, it just
went down the wrong pipe.
You know, I think
maybe with everything
that's gone down
with Sonaris and all,
it'd be better if I could
deal with them directly.
You know Cameron.
If I can keep you out of it,
maybe we can spare
ourselves her wrath.
Yeah, sure.
No problem.
Great, so we can set
something up soon?
This week?
Yeah.
You know what?
Actually the person
I've been dealing with
over there is Joe.
Ahem.
Joe who?
( theme music playing )
- Man: Incoming!
- ( glass shatters )
- ( coders laughing )
- Oh, come on, now.
( music playing
in background )
Duck!
Gracious,
is that a pajama top?
- Well, what
is a pajama top, John?
- ( groans )
I mean, if you fall
asleep in that shirt,
does it become
a pajama top?
And then can it ever not be
a pajama top once it is--
I'm just askin'
when you bought it,
did it come with bottoms?
What constitutes bottoms?
Okay, forget I asked.
Yeah, it's cool,
but you know what
I'm gonna say.
Oh, come on.
Look, it's good guys
versus bad guys.
Yeah, but why
are they bad?
Why do we care?
What's the context?
Cont-- a roller coaster
doesn't have any context.
- Tom...
- What? No one gets off
Judge Roy Scream
talking about the story.
They talk about the experience.
- A roller coaster's
90 seconds long.
- ( doorbell rings )
You have to create
something here that's gonna
consume people for hours.
- You know I'm right.
- Cameron?
( imitates Terminator )
I'll be back.
( both laugh )
Oh, God. What?
What do you want?
As you know, I am
a long-standing Mutiny user,
so I trust
you'll give my input
the weight it is due.
- Okay, get on with it.
- Yesterday evening,
I was playing "Parallax."
Chapter eight,
challenge four.
- On the path...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
...I solved the riddle
and yet I wasn't able
to continue on.
Either this is a glitch
or an illogical piece
of in-game storytelling.
Whatever the case,
I would like like a refund
for that hour of usage.
You're not
getting shit, buddy.
We don't give refunds
for people who are too thick
to figure out the game,
and even if we did,
you haven't paid your bill
in two months,
so you're operating
on borrowed time as it is.
Now, if I were you,
I'd head back to
chapter eight
and maybe consider
my dwindling water reserves
and see where in the game
I could've replenished
my supply.
Oh!
Bye!
- ( door opens, closes )
- ( phone ringing )
- Chet?
- Yeah.
But it just makes
no damn sense.
I want a cup of coffee--
look, cups are clear
across the kitchen, huh?
See?
Now where's the sugar?
Again, all the way
across the kitchen.
Come on, man.
I'm bouncing around
like a damn pinball.
Now, look, create a station.
One-stop, all your needs.
Do you know what
I'm talking about?
- Coffee?
- ( both laugh )
Oh, God.
Efficiency, son.
Time is money.
For-- get outta here.
You're amazing, Boz.
Hey, who was that
bothering you?
Huh? Oh, Chet.
He's a user.
He's just some
pain in the ass.
Hey, what about
vertical space?
We could have
these vertical tubes that
you climb up, you drop down...
Yeah, that's amazing.
But you know what
I'm gonna say--
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just check it out.
- Just check it out.
- Well, then, figure it out.
( sighs )
You lied to your wife.
That's not my problem.
Oh, but it is.
She's gonna tell
Cameron, all right?
They want a sit-down
with a representative
from Westgroup.
They want a formal
agreement in writing.
Look, you gotta make
this thing legitimate.
- That's not possible.
- Well, then, make it possible.
It's only been three weeks.
The whole plan was to amass
months of data.
- We don't have a choice.
- We've always got a choice.
I can kick Mutiny
off the network and go
to another online service.
You can, but you're
not going to
because we had
a deal, right, Joe?
And you're gonna honor
that agreement
because you're not
the reptilian son of a bitch
that everybody
says you are.
- You're a changed man.
- This isn't what I wanted.
If I tell Wheeler too early
and he doesn't go for it,
the network is done,
- Mutiny is done.
- Snap out of it, all right?
You're Joe MacMillan.
You could talk him into
jumping off a bridge
if you wanted to.
Just decide
to do it and do it.
Look, I gotta go.
- Just promise me
that you're gonna--
- Got it.
- ( door opens, closes )
- ( sighs )
Ahem.
What's going on?
I want to emphasize
that I had no idea
about this,
and as soon as I found out,
I came straight here.
What?
Joe MacMillan is the person
running the network.
He's Gordon's contact
at the company.
I'm sorry?
Gordon helped him
set up time-sharing.
He insisted that Mutiny
get a good deal,
- and he didn't tell me--
- Stop.
You let Joe MacMillan
in the door?
I didn't do anything.
No, Gordon, again.
- I'm sorry, Donna,
but he doesn't work here.
- I know.
- This isn't his
to mess with.
- I know.
He wanted to make up
for crashing the network.
Huh.
What a way to apologize.
He felt terrible.
He wanted to fix it.
I know this isn't
any consolation,
but I sat across from Joe.
He seems... different.
Maybe he's changed.
Thank you
for your honesty.
If you don't mind, I'd like
a few moments to myself.
Okay.
- ( Cameron screams )
- ( loud clattering )
Um, based on my
examination last time--
the symmetrical weakness
in your hands, the memory
and concentration tests,
your employment history,
um, exposure to lead solder,
and working with solvents--
I ordered the MRI.
I know you were
a little ambivalent
about the test,
but I am glad
that we sprung for it
because it really is
an amazing new tool.
According to the radiologists,
there are two areas,
very small,
that show signs of atrophy.
Atrophy?
Brain damage.
It's chronic toxic
encephalopathy.
- ( gasps )
- Now, given this
combination of clues,
it explains
your physical symptoms
and it likely accounts
for the psychological symptoms
you described
to me as well--
irritability
and the mood swings.
Yeah, how do I fix it?
I'm sorry to say
there is no treatment.
Brain tissue
does not repair itself.
This will be
a permanent condition.
( stammers )
But I feel fine.
What the hell's
gonna happen now?
Well, your symptoms
could likely progress.
- This could get worse?
- This was years of slow
accumulation
of these toxins
in your blood.
But in light of that,
the fact that
your symptoms
have accelerated
would indicate that
you likely haven't seen
the worst of this yet.
I am sorry, Gordon.
- ( keyboard clacking )
- ( music playing
in background )
So, what's going on
with Cameron?
Do you remember
Joe MacMillan?
- Sure, Admiral Eyebrows.
- What?
That's what we called him.
You didn't call him that?
No, but I will now.
Anyway, turns out
he's the one who's
running the network.
That sucks.
She mutinied to get
away from that psycho.
Mm. Who are you
talking to, Lev?
Nobody.
It's none of your business.
It's just a friend.
Who you talking to, Lev?
It's just a guy I met
in one of the forums.
We've-- we've been talking.
He likes the Cure.
- You've been flirting.
- So?
Lev, this is good.
This is really good.
We're gonna make
a room where you can
meet people online.
- Meet?
- Yes.
- Like girls?
- Yes!
We'll do a personals room
where you meet
and then you go
into a private room,
like a date.
She got the idea from Lev
'cause he's been talking
to someone online.
- ( all laugh )
- Oh, great.
You see, I've been
living in the past,
taking a woman out to dinner
like we used to do.
- You got a date, Boz?
- Now, I'm not sure
why that news
is met with such
shock and disbelief.
Looks like you're talking
to a fella there, Lev.
Yeah.
Oh.
Yeah, okay.
No, so you're--
no, that's completely,
uh-- yeah.
Oh, hell,
I got a cousin.
Ahem.
- ( phone ringing )
- Good.
I'm gonna get
another coffee here.
- Yeah.
- Coder: Hey, Donna,
it's Gordon!
Hello?
- Hey, sweetie.
- What's up?
- I was, uh--
- What are we gonna call
the private rooms?
I don't know,
A Table For Two?
- Barf.
- Okay, fine,
then you figure it out.
Sorry, what
were you saying?
Where are you?
It's loud.
I've, uh--
I just got the TV on.
Why don't we go out tonight,
just the two of us?
No kids?
It's been a while
since we spent some time
together just you and me.
- Donna?
- Yeah, sorry.
I lost you for a second.
That sounds great.
We just really hit
on something
and I think we're probably
gonna be working late, so...
Yeah, yeah,
of course.
Um, but maybe
this weekend sometime?
- Sure.
- Sorry, look,
I gotta jump off,
but I'll see you
at home, okay?
- I love you, bye.
- Yeah, yeah, I love you t--
( dial tone )
Hey, Tom,
you coming?
- Coder: Sounds cool.
- Coder #2: Shotgun.
- Yeah.
- Coder: Aw, man!
Hey, um, do you know
what's going on with her?
- With Cameron?
- Stuff with her ex.
It's a long story.
Come on, let's go.
Ah!
( laughs )
Come on, sobachka.
You dog.
Coder:
Grab my keys!
Coder #2:
This is gonna be awesome!
( staple gun clicking )
Hey, champ.
What's shakin'?
( sighs )
Oh, Jesus!
This stupid chair.
Hey, Cam?
- Cam?
- What?
Come on, let's talk.
Joe:
I've calculated the cost
of every barrel of oil
you pull out of the ground.
It takes an awful lot of money
to make that first dollar.
Using your existing
mainframe for time-sharing,
there's no cost to you.
There's an ocean
of money out there
and you have already
drilled the wells.
People talk about
the computer revolution
as if it were
a thing of the past,
but I grew up
running around IBM.
This business
is in my blood,
and believe me
when I tell you,
the revolution hasn't
even started yet.
I think it sounds...
promising.
I thought you would.
That's why I did it
three weeks ago.
I retrofitted
the mainframe.
I sold the time
to an exciting company
called Mutiny.
In three weeks,
they've shown
steady growth
and will only
continue to expand.
This could be the moment
when Westgroup stops
digging in the past
and starts
building the future.
All you have to do...
is nothing.
Three weeks of data,
that's not much.
- The trend will continue.
- Maybe. Have a seat, Joe.
So, you did all this
behind my back.
That was quite a gamble.
You know, Westgroup
is a huge operation.
However, one resource
sorely lacking
in a company
of this size
is hunger.
Everybody here
is fat and happy.
But you?
You strike me
as the kind of guy
that isn't ever satisfied.
You aren't happy,
and I can turn that
into money.
I assume this takes you
out of Data Entry.
It would. I would be
the network administrator
managing
the sales of the time,
the hardware upkeep.
And I suppose a nice raise
comes along with a new title.
No raise.
Let me show you
that it works first.
Huh.
Sara knew
all about this, huh?
She's got
some poker face.
Yeah.
I just want
to have a meeting
with somebody from,
what was it? Mutiny?
Let's have a sit-down
tomorrow night.
I'm flying up to Alaska
around 7:00, but we can
meet before then.
Uh, you don't have to worry.
I can handle the client.
Oh, I'm not worried.
We'll meet tomorrow night.
I never go
into business with anyone
without looking them
in the eye first.
Cameron:
Well, I want to kill him.
I know you don't like Joe.
Neither do I.
I'd like to see him
punched in the balls
as much as anybody,
but he's a businessman,
and not a bad one.
Put together Giant,
got me onboard.
That box
was an abomination.
From a strictly
commercial standpoint,
pulling your operating system
was the right move.
That machine,
it meant a lot to me.
It wasn't art,
but it was sound business,
and one thing about Mutiny
is you got a whole lot
of the former,
not much of the latter.
Look, to top it all off,
you got Joe right where
you want him.
You kidding me?
He wants forgiveness.
He wants to do right by you.
I just feel like
we're part of some plan
that he has.
The only person I trust
to get an accurate read
on Joe MacMillan-- that's you.
You gotta look him
in the eye.
And if I don't like
what I see?
Then you kill him.
( chuckles )
"I.O.U." playing
- ( music blaring )
- ( clubbers chattering )
( clubbers cheering )
♪ A-E-A-E-I-O-U-U ♪
♪ I sometimes cry ♪
♪ You tell me
that you love me every day ♪
♪ When we're alone,
I really feel in love ♪
♪ But when we're out
with friends, I see a change ♪
♪ You treat me bad,
I feel like second best... ♪
( echoing )
♪ I want your love,
give me your love ♪
♪ That's how I feel,
I want it to be real ♪
♪ I want your love,
give me your love ♪
♪ I need your touch
and I owe you so much ♪
♪ A-E-A-E-I-O... ♪
Smile!
Why aren't you dancing?
I have brain damage!
Oh, never heard of them.
I think I'm dying!
Oh, me, too!
Whoo!
( music continues )
Why didn't you
tell me beforehand?
In case
it didn't work out.
I didn't want
to fall on my face
in front of you.
How did you
even do it?
Gordon helped me
with the setup.
He did
some of the hardware
on the condition
that I lease the time
to the company where
Donna works.
They need
a competitive price.
Cameron's company.
( scoffs )
The plot thickens.
It was Gordon's
stipulation.
You know how this looks.
- Yeah.
- Bad.
It looks bad.
I would've told you,
but I wanted to show you
the finished product.
It was stupid,
but I thought you'd
be impressed.
I am.
We don't keep secrets.
I don't care how small.
I can't do it.
"Where are you" playing
♪ Can you ♪
♪ Or me... ♪
( laughter )
♪ Save anyone... ♪
- Morning.
♪ From disappearing? ♪
- ( retching )
- ♪ The shape ♪
♪ Of time ♪
- ♪ The shade of light... ♪
- ( toilet flushes )
♪ Receding... ♪
( doorbell rings )
Joe, lovely to see you.
Is Donna home?
I'm not sure you really
want to talk to her.
Donna doesn't, uh--
I don't know how
to put this-- like you.
Donna does not like you.
I need to speak to her.
Gordon:
Okay.
Gordon, who was that?
It's for you.
Hi.
Joe:
I've set up a meeting
with Jacob Wheeler.
He's looking forward
to sitting down with you.
- Me specifically?
- A representative
from Mutiny.
I thought you were
the obvious choice given
your hardware background.
And because
I'm not Cameron.
That would be a little awkward,
but that's not why I'm here.
Look, Joe,
it's not my company.
You need to deal with her.
I expect her
to be prepared
and I expect her
to be professional.
It's Mutiny's future
on the line here, too.
You tell me where and when,
I'll make sure she shows up.
( Joe sighs )
( door opens, closes )
I didn't hear you
come home last night.
Cameron flipped
when I told her about Joe.
I had to stay
and hold down the fort.
Do you want
to get some lunch?
Maybe we could go
pick up the girls
together.
You know I'm dealing
with a lot of stuff right now.
I-- I have to go
back to work.
I have to talk
to Cameron, again.
I'm sorry.
I'd like to say
a few things before--
Hi, are they ready for us?
Receptionist:
One moment, please.
The hardware wars
are over.
The future
is in connection.
Mutiny has
cutting edge games,
people meeting and competing
in a virtual world.
Wheeler:
Sounds like Playnet
is doing the same thing,
as far as I can tell.
- No.
- No?
We create a fully
interactive experience.
They make a pretty good
version of hangman.
- ( chuckles )
- We're not doing
the same thing as Playnet.
We don't want to do
We're doing something
much, much better with
half the resources.
- And how do you
pull that off?
- Our code's better.
It's more efficient
and creative.
( laughs )
So, tell me,
how does someone get good
at something like that?
Uh...
( laughs )
How did Gretzky
get good at hockey?
- Practice.
- And?
And a whole lot
of God-given talent.
- It's your words, not mine.
- ( chuckles )
Here, let me show you.
I didn't make you
for a hockey fan.
- I like the fights.
- Hmm.
So this is
just a demo disk,
but it'll give you
some idea
of what our interface
looks like.
Okay.
- Gordon: How was school?
- Girls: Good.
Yeah?
You guys wanna
go have some fun
with your dad?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
You tell me.
We can do
anything you want.
Let's go to
Grandma and Grandpa's
- and play video games!
- Yeah!
You don't understand.
We could do anything.
We could go to the park,
we could go to the zoo,
we could go
to the movies,
you know?
You name it.
Huh?
Um, let's go to
Grandma and Grandpa's.
You guys were
just there yesterday.
Come on, be creative.
Anything you want, all right?
- Hi!
- Grandma!
- You sure this is
all right, Susan?
Of course!
Mm.
I appreciate it.
You know, I asked them
where they wanted to go,
do whatever they want.
They are positively
obsessed
with this thing
Gary brought back
from his trip.
The Japs love him.
Gave him one of those
arcade game video things
you plug into your TV.
It's not being released
until the fall.
Hey, sweethearts,
what is that contraption
called?
- Girls: A Nintendo!
- Nintendo!
- Mm.
- It's a bunch of little men
fighting turtles or something.
I don't-- can't follow it.
I don't understand the appeal.
Um, can I offer you
a drink?
Sure.
- Thank you.
- Well, great.
I'm impressed.
So what about this guy?
You two know
each other from your stint
at Cardiff Electric, right?
Can you vouch for him?
He's marrying my daughter.
He's a hell of a guy.
Congratulations.
Uh, Cameron, wait.
I just wanted to say
you were great in there
and it was nice
to see you.
( scoffs )
You know, when I heard that
you had weaseled your way
back into my life,
I was pissed.
But more than that,
I was scared because
I thought I was the mark.
He's the mark, isn't he?
He's not a mark.
I don't--
it's an honest
business proposal.
I can't tell if you know
you're lying or not.
- I'm not lying.
- Okay.
So it's just a coincidence
that you fell in love with
the daughter of a billionaire.
Why can't you see
that I'm helping you here?
I never asked for help.
I don't want any help,
especially from you.
Joe:
Listen, a lot has changed
since I saw you last.
Yeah, I'm not the same
naive girl anymore.
So just stay away.
Did you get my letter?
Did you read it?
( footsteps approach )
- Hi.
- Uh...
You must be Cameron.
Oh, sorry.
Cameron, this is Sara.
Sara, this is Cameron.
- The fiancée, of course.
- Yeah.
- Congrats.
- Thank you.
Uh, Joe told me
all about your company.
It's very interesting.
- Mm-hmm.
- We should all have dinner.
I'd love to learn
more about it.
We'll have
to make that happen.
Uh, it was lovely
to meet you.
Joe, always a pleasure.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah, it was great.
Clearly.
"Super Mario Bros"
theme playing
- ( laughing )
- You're fun, Gordon.
How come I never knew
you were so much fun?
I am fun.
I'm super fun.
It's that Donna
that keeps me down.
( laughs )
She takes after her dad.
God, me and her
used to have such
a good time together.
You know, when we
first got together and
we'd come visit you guys,
we'd always end up
at this bar/club type
place, the Twist,
and we would dance
till we were just
about dead.
You know,
shut the place down.
- My Donna?
- Oh, yeah.
I mean, when we moved here,
we thought we'd be going
there all the time,
but, you know,
the kids and, you know,
life gets in the way
and you just forget
to have fun.
- Mm.
- But, you know,
fun's important.
- To fun.
Haley:
I can't see.
How am I supposed
to get back?
Mm.
You know...
I never really
thanked you properly.
You and Gary
have been so good to us.
You know, done so much.
It took us a while
to land on our feet,
but you supported us
throughout.
You know, and now
it's finally paid off.
Susan, we couldn't have
done it without you.
Well, what's the point
of having money
if not to help out
your loved ones?
Well, I don't mean
the money.
I just mean, you know,
being there for us.
Oh.
Yeah.
Well, what, you want me
to pay you back?
( laughs )
I thought that's what--
I'm sorry,
I feel awkward.
Oh, you want me
to pay you back?
Well, all that talk
of family and support
and you having money now,
I just...
I think you've had
too much to drink,
sweetheart.
Oh, no, no, no.
What do we owe you?
Donna will never
owe us a cent.
But the Symphonic?
We put in just north
of 22,000, all told.
I got my checkbook.
Uh, just north
of 22, 000, you say.
Mm-hmm.
Why don't we make it
an even 23?
( pen clicks )
- Oh.
- ( laughs )
You know,
my girlfriends and I
went on a wine tasting,
and you know how that is.
( laughs )
One thing leads
to another.
What?
What was the charge?
( whispers )
Indecent exposure.
Oh, my God.
I'm absolutely
scandalized.
( quietly )
I'm sorry, sir.
Can I speak to you a moment?
Yeah, sure.
- Just one moment.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry, sir.
Your card is declined.
Declined?
- Let me talk
to the manager.
- I am the manager.
Look, I used to come here
all the time.
- I'm friends with Silvio.
- He retired.
( stammers )
Look, I'm good for it.
I'll be here first thing
tomorrow with a fat wad
of cash and a hefty tip.
You have my word.
- Well, can't she pay?
- No, she cannot pay.
- She is my date.
- Come on, man.
It's 1985.
Come on.
Give me a second
to work something out,
all right?
All right.
Hi.
( dial tone )
( music playing
in background )
Guys, Chet's entering rooms
through other people's accounts
and he's cursing out Bosworth
for kicking him off the network.
- ( laughing )
- It's hilarious.
( phone ringing )
Mutiny.
Hey.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- I'll pay you back.
Yeah, that's cool.
I'll see you a little later.
- Hey.
- Uh-huh?
How'd you like
your new chair?
Did you kick Chet
off the network?
Yeah.
Why did you do that?
He was in arrears.
He couldn't pay.
I think you'd have
some sympathy for that.
Oh, shit, Cameron,
come on, you know
what I mean.
You said he was
a pain in the ass.
It's a business.
No, it's a community.
It's my community.
And we don't
kick people out.
It sends a message, okay?
He's been with us
since day one.
He's loyal.
Yeah, he's a pain in the ass,
but I like being annoyed by him
and I like
my shitty chair.
I just... want everyone
to leave Mutiny alone.
It's mine.
( touch tones beeping )
- ( line rings )
- Man: Hello?
Is this
Henry's House of Dildos?
Ah, yes, Mr. Clark.
Your order of extra small
condoms just arrived.
- ( laughs )
- How are you, Hank?
I'm good, buddy.
How are you?
I'm gettin' by.
How are the kids?
They smell terrible,
they're filthy,
they talk back.
It's no way to live.
Yeah, well, I got
a couple of angels.
- Got their mother's looks.
- Yeah, thank God for that.
So, what's up?
You just calling
to bust some balls or what?
Well, I was thinking
about visiting,
you know,
bringing the girls.
That's a great idea.
I'm sure Mom and Dad
would like to see you, too,
if you want to make
the drive over there.
You really
want me to come?
You're not
just saying that?
Don't be stupid.
Of course I do.
I miss the hell
outta you, Gordo.
Yeah, it'd be great
to talk, catch up.
Yeah.
Yeah, it would be.
- ( pops )
- ( coders laughing )
( door opens )
Oh, hey.
How was your date?
I've had better.
- Oh.
- God.
- ( taps top )
- ( pops )
You know, I think
you should talk to Cameron.
Hmm?
I think she's going through
some stuff right now
I think you could
help her with.
What do mean?
None of my damn business,
but I think she might
be pregnant.
Uh, why do you think that?
( distant dog barking )
I found a pregnancy kit
in the trash out back.
I don't know.
Yeah.
No, I...
it wasn't Cameron's.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Cyborgs don't feel pain.
I do.
Don't do that again.
- Just let me go.
- Listen and understand!
That Terminator
is out there.
It can't be bargained with,
it can't be reasoned with...
- Dude, sit down.
- ...it doesn't feel pity...
- Move.
- Lev: Sit down, fatass.
Kyle on TV:
And it absolutely
will not stop, ever...
- Amit: Brodie,
get out of the way!
- ...until you are dead!
( all laughing )
Yeah!
- All right, I gotta go.
- Where you goin'?
- Gotta go?
- I have a date.
And not in a Community room,
but with an actual living,
breathing woman.
- Coders: Ooh!
- I'll see you guys tomorrow.
Yeah, do it!
- Have fun.
- ( zips bag )
- ( tires squealing on TV )
- ( door opens, closes )
Turn to the last page.
- Why?
- Just turn to
the last page.
The only thing
I'm after is you.
I think we need
to slow things down.
I think it's all
going too fast.
I just need some room
to figure it out.
- Is this about Cameron?
- No, it's about you.
And maybe
it's about me, too.
I don't know.
- I just need some time.
- Time? What does that mean?
- I'm going back to Austin.
- For how long?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
( crying )
( knocks on window )
This is how
it should start.
You should have to crawl
through a ventilation shaft
or something.
I think they bought it.
What's wrong?
( sniffles )
Nothing.
( music playing )