"Lucky I Got What I Want"
playing
♪ I steal living ♪
♪ Tell me I'm wrong ♪
♪ Will I be forgiven ♪
♪ If I wanna walk
like you? ♪
♪ Swingin' it back
when I want... ♪
- ( answering machine beeps )
- It's me again.
Are you there?
Uh, I come home...
and I can tell
you've been here.
Sometimes it's an empty bottle
on the counter or...
suddenly some of your clothes
go missing.
I feel like you want me
to see these things,
to notice,
and I do
and I call,
and you don't pick up.
It's been a week.
I love you.
Call me back.
( sighs )
( rings )
- Sara?
- It's Jacob.
Business Development
has made
a few last-minute tweaks
in the Mutiny contract
and I want it out the door
by this afternoon.
I was just going over it.
Um, specifically
what kind of tweaks
are we talking about?
But jumping Mutiny's
hourly rate from $3 to $5
would hamstring their growth.
- Say they have a bad month--
- That's not our problem.
According to
Business Development,
the going
market rate is $5
We have to set a precedent
for our future clients.
It's all found money
to Westgroup.
What difference
does it make if we offer
a temporary exemption?
Why are you so anxious
to give this company
a break, Joe?
I hope it's not
your past relationship
to the founder.
Absolutely not.
Mutiny's our pilot program.
We both took a risk.
They got a corresponding
discount.
Look, I like Cameron,
but I liked the deal
you pitched me a lot more.
A bunch of companies
give us free money
to use our network
when we aren't.
You're my
building manager, Joe.
And I only want the tenants
who pay the highest rent.
Jacob, I respectfully
disagree.
With Mutiny,
I see our role
as much more hands-on.
This is a company
with a real potential
to innovate.
There's a lot
of talent there,
but it's raw.
It needs shaping,
guidance.
That's where we come in.
Okay, start out at $5.
Go down to four,
if you have to,
but 3.50
is the absolute bottom.
If they don't sign,
move on.
( children playing )
Gordon:
Yeah, right here.
Thanks so much.
They're here!
Landshark!
Henry:
Well, if it isn't
Alfred Einstein!
I can't believe
you got off of your butt,
put your feet
to the ground,
and you actually
showed up.
- Get over here.
- ( both groaning )
Oh!
Joanie and Haley?
Wh-- you girls
must have aged 100 years
since I last saw you.
- ( giggles )
- Yeah, thank God they got
their mother's looks.
Hey, Jody, Michael,
take your cousins
to the back and--
- New trampoline!
Come on!
- Wow!
- I'll go.
- It's really bouncy!
- Michael: Come on,
you guys!
- Ah.
How you doin', man?
You all right?
You up and flew
out here awful fast.
Not that I'm not
thrilled to see you.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Huh?
- We'll get into it
a little later, yeah?
- Yeah.
Tada.
Oh, thank you
for getting those.
Joanie practically refused
to go to California
without 'em.
Found them stuck
in the corner pockets
of your father's pool table.
( laughs )
- Are okay, honey?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just have to get to work.
Well, I'm glad you
at least took the morning.
You looked tired
as a dog, for one thing,
and I haven't even heard
from you since Easter.
Gordon's been by
with the girls--
Yeah, well, Gordon
has a thing called
free time.
How about you tell me
what's really going on?
Is it you and Gordon?
Are you two having
problems again?
I, uh--
I was pregnant,
but I, uh, lost it.
I... miscarried.
Oh, my God, Donna.
Honey, I'm so sorry.
You know, I-- wait,
I wasn't very far along
and I was waiting for
the right time to tell Gordon,
but then it...
You know, it's okay.
It wasn't planned.
Like you said,
I'm so underwater
with work as it is
and Gordon and I are
already practically leading
separate lives, so...
You know,
it'll get easier.
But it'll take time.
I love
the children we have.
You know, it really wouldn't
have been fair to them.
It was a really special time
when they were small,
but we are in
a different place now,
our family
feels complete,
and so...
maybe in a way--
maybe this is what's best.
10 bucks says
they're at it right now.
If I had 10 bucks to burn,
you think I'd be back here
wrestling coax,
trying to steal us HBO?
- ( electricity crackles )
- Damn it!
- Told you.
- All right, 10 bucks.
- Follow me.
- ( music playing
in background )
( laughing )
( knock on door )
Lev:
A sub breached the network.
He broke into
the autoexec.bat file
and now he's giving out
free user IDs.
- Oh, shit!
- Come quick! Go.
Cameron:
Coming! Just one second!
How many, uh, IDs?
- ( whispers )
I'll see you at work.
- Bye.
( door slams )
( laughing )
( coders laughing )
( clapping )
Aw, man!
I missed it!
That's good.
Back to work, guys.
Come on.
He wears boxers.
- Guys!
- ( music playing
in background )
So this is Mutiny.
( theme music playing )
( pages flipping )
$5 an hour is unmanageable.
Actually, it's insane.
If we have one bad month
or if we're doing well and
we want to make new hires,
this leaves
no room for error.
This feels like
a bait and switch.
Of course
it's a bait and switch.
- It's Joe MacMillan.
- That's not our intent.
- With Jacob Wheeler
involved, things changed.
- Your fiancée's dad.
They evolved.
This was out of my control.
Yeah, you evolved
back into an asshole.
Oh, but look, he held out
three whole days, so hat's off.
Okay, message received.
I wanted to do the courtesy
of coming here in person,
but there are certainly
other companies
who are interested in
your space on our network.
- I'll reach out
to one of them.
- No, look.
Just give us a minute.
Am I the only one
that sees what's
happening here?
First he's the man
behind the network,
now he's changing
our deal terms?
- What's next?
- Look, I don't
like it either.
But his network
is the best thing
to happen to us,
and right now we need him
more than he needs us.
Yes, and he knows it.
Yes, but if you
can keep your cool,
I can get us a number
we can live with
and then he's back to being
a name on the 12th page
of our contract, right?
Fine.
So, uh...
you and Cameron
worked together
at Cardiff, huh?
We did.
She must be
an interesting boss.
She knows
what she wants.
You ran PCs for them?
I've been knocking around
tech for a long time,
always working
to the next new thing.
- Well,
time-sharing's not that new.
- Time-sharing's just a way in.
CompuServe
started as a division
of a life insurance company,
then got bought by H&amp;R Block
who wanted to diversify.
Now it's a 500-pound gorilla
in the world of commercial
online service.
Who knows where Westgroup
can take it from there?
Yeah.
So, how are you guys
handling security?
Are you multiplexing
them in from an SNA network
from the modem banks
with task-switching--
Comes a time when vision
meets engineering--
you hire people.
Thanks for the coffee.
So, you've said
your party line,
I've said mine.
Let's cut the posturing
and we'll get down to
the real number.
- $5.
- Donna: Joe.
- It's $5.
- No.
No, this is where you say
4.50 and then I say 3.50,
and then eventually
we settle on four,
which is fair.
$4.
$5.
This isn't a negotiation.
You started
at a promotional rate.
- I'm sorry,
this isn't a negotiation?
- That promotion is over.
If you don't agree
to the $5 terms,
- Westgroup is moving on.
- Moving on?
- That's-- that's not--
- Charity? No, it's not.
This is a partnership.
Jacob Wheeler isn't interested
in a typical landlord-tenant
relationship with you.
He wants to work
with innovative companies
who are agile and committed.
$5 is the ante
for this table.
If Mutiny can't compete
at the going market rate,
maybe it shouldn't be
in the game.
( Donna crying )
Donna?
( crying continues )
This is bullshit!
Joe, this is bullshit!
All you own is time
on a network.
What entitles you
to have an opinion about
anything that we do here?
What makes you think
that you can question
our commitment
- for one dollar an hour?
- ( glass shatters )
- Calm down.
- I'm fine, I'm fine.
God...
Maybe being in bed
with a billionaire--
I'm sorry, with
a billionaire's daughter
makes you think
- that you can jerk us around
for your own amusement...
- Donna.
...but this is real to us.
So it's $4, Joe.
It's $4.
( exhales sharply )
- ( Cameron stammers ) Just--
- Don't bother.
( door opens )
- It's fine.
- ( door closes )
He's gonna call
in three hours
and he's gonna say $4.
He's bluffing.
- So, that's where I'm at.
- ( music playing
in background )
Uh, look...
anything
you need, okay?
Anything at all,
you just say the word, okay?
And the girls,
they can come
stay with us,
or I could fly out
if you need, you know?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Jesus, Gordon.
Hey, hey, hey.
Seriously, it's okay,
all right?
I know it's a shock.
I shouldn't have
laid it all on you
at once like that.
Jesus, I'm sorry.
I should be the one
comforting...
What can I do?
Hey, Henry,
you're already
doing it, okay?
It's all right.
Oh.
Donna must be a mess
with all this going on.
Actually, uh,
she doesn't know.
- Gordon--
- Look, you have no idea
what the last year
has been like.
I mean, you know,
her work's taking off,
you know, and it's
driving her, you know,
like-- well, like mine
used to, you know?
She's happy, okay?
She's energized.
And she'd stop everything
to take care of me
and I can't ask her
to do that.
Not-- not yet,
at least.
So, um, if we had to
switch back to XTs,
how long would
that take?
We're not gonna
have to do it.
Okay, but just
in case we do,
- just round number it for me.
- Look, I'm sorry, okay?
I don't know what else
you want me to say.
- ( door opens )
- Guys?
What?
- It's not the modem.
- ( coders clamoring )
What is it?
What happened?
Joe MacMillan happened!
He pulled the plug!
So I guess
he wasn't bluffing.
Okay, okay, okay.
Um, so do you want
to call him, maybe,
or are you just
gonna cry again?
- Bosworth: That's enough.
- Come on, Donna.
The name on page 12
of our contract just
shut our company down
- because of your great
negotiation skills!
- Bosworth: Cameron.
Could you have had your day
on the rag when the entire
network wasn't at stake?
I said that's enough,
damn it!
God, what is wrong
with you?
I'm--
I'm gonna fix it.
( music playing
in background )
Oh, the shop's been slippin'
the last few years.
I still think
we can pull it out,
but Dad wants to sell it,
let it get turned into a Midas.
- Where does that leave you?
- I'd stay on, work for
the new owners.
Oh, come on,
that doesn't seem right.
I'm gonna call him,
tell him he's making
a mistake.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
You've-- you've got enough
on your plate right now.
Oh, what time
is it?
- Hoohoo!
- Should we settle up?
You know, go give
Wendy some relief?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
I'm gonna go hit the head.
You wanna get the--
( whistles )
Excuse me,
can we get our tab?
- Ju-- Jules Duffy?
- Gordon. I'll be damned.
Thought you'd gone
all rich and famous on us.
Yeah, I got my plane
parked out back.
- ( chuckles )
- I'm here with Henry.
Yeah, I see
plenty of Henry.
You two still trying
to get back what you
had in high school?
Nope, just trying to get him
to pay his bar tab every
once in a blue moon.
Hey, you remember that time
that I caught you and Henry
breaking into
Dad's liquor cabinet?
Y'all made me drink
a coffee cup full of brandy
just so I couldn't
tell on you?
No. Did it work?
God, I nearly died
the next morning.
( laughs )
The house is still there.
You can come by anytime.
Yeah, I'll just crawl
into Henry's old window,
scare his kids,
leave mine alone.
- You have kids?
- He's 12.
- You have 12 kids?
- I have one kid,
12 years old.
- Oh.
- He's my anchor. R.J.
Jules Duffy,
married with a kid.
Well, half right.
Single mom.
All right,
pay up, pecker.
Heard you got rich,
so big tip.
What the hell
was that about?
- You're asking me?
- Yeah.
She lost it.
Now we're dead.
All Donna did was behave
like you do every day
without bailing you out
for it like usual.
- You know, maybe
you didn't like it...
- I never--
...because it was like
looking in a damn mirror!
People have other things
going on in their lives
that you
don't know about.
And you do, huh?
Can't you see
that that woman
is going through
something?
She could use
a friend right now.
( computers humming )
I was out of line
and I apologize.
This work--
this work means
a lot to me.
And if we accept your deal,
we're risking our survival,
and if we don't,
we could scramble
for months
to try and find
another network.
Months in this business
could crush us.
That's not
what you want, is it?
- If this
is about Cameron--
- It's not.
Then to pull the plug
over one dollar,
that's what you do
when you're trying
to get out of a deal.
Which is where
we find ourselves now.
Well, I can't leave here
until we work this out,
so you tell me.
What can I do?
( exhales )
Maybe-- uh, maybe I could
find some wiggle room
on the price
if Mutiny met
a few, um...
strategic benchmarks.
Benchmarks.
For example,
when I log onto Mutiny,
the main screen,
it's boring.
There's a company in Houston
that has news and weather
as soon as you log on.
Delphi has
a travel agency.
There's an outfit
in Galveston
that has a stock ticker
updated hourly.
That's the kind of thing
that makes me the user
want to stay longer.
We can do that.
Another thing--
check out the messaging
available on something
like IBM's Vnet.
Mail programs
have been around
for over a decade.
Exactly.
Why doesn't
Mutiny have one?
Because that's not--
We can do mail
and we can
do the interface,
and if we do...
He's not gonna like it,
but I, uh, bet I could
get Jacob
to shave off a buck
for one last thing.
What?
What is it that you need?
Mutiny currently
runs exclusively
on Commodore 64s, right?
64s will be
boat anchors by '88.
In the meantime,
UNIX is poised to explode.
If Mutiny could port
to a machine that runs UNIX,
say the new AT&amp;T box,
I think I could justify
a lower price.
But UNIX
is a completely different
operating system.
That's a major
coding overhaul--
In fact, I would go
so far as to plug you
back in right now,
- ink the contract
at $5...
- But--
...and add a provision
that once you meet
these benchmarks,
we'll drop it down
to 3.50.
I'll see what I can do.
UNIX?
Christ.
I think he knew
he wanted these benchmarks
before he ever came
over here this morning.
It was all
just about leverage.
Yeah.
Well, I guess it was
a negotiation after all.
But the AT&amp;T
isn't even in color.
Hey, let's look
at the bright side.
I guess we'll have
stock ticker and mail now.
Great, we'll be
bleeding edge for 1979.
You know,
there are blueprints
to build mail out
because it's been
around forever.
It wouldn't
take that long.
- Cool. Thanks.
- Just trying to help.
Look, I just-- I don't know
what choice we have.
You could fake UNIX.
Make it look like Mutiny
is running on the AT&amp;T,
get your better rate
locked in now,
actually go multiplatform
at your leisure.
I talked to him this morning
and he knows the script, sure,
but his actual tech knowledge
is really limited.
If you get him in here
tomorrow morning
and you sit him down at a demo,
and if it looked real enough--
No, the boot and interface
screens for the 64 and the AT&amp;T
are completely different.
Yeah, but we can paint
the screens however we want.
I mean, write a Commodore
program that makes it look
just like the AT&amp;T.
But Joe would know that porting
to an OS like UNIX would take
longer than 24 hours.
Would he?
What, you're gonna
say, "Bad idea"?
It is a bad idea.
So we run the demo
off a C64
and we don't invite him
till tomorrow night.
The goal is simple:
replace the guts
of this AT&amp;T box
with those of a Commodore,
hook up the video cards inside
to the monochrome CRT.
When Joe boots up,
he'll think he's running UNIX,
but really it'll be our 64.
A wolf in UNIX clothing.
Okay, screwdriver.
The thing only has enough room
for an internal serial modem.
How the hell are we supposed
to fit an external
Hayes box inside?
- Let alone
the Commodore cards.
- We could lay the cards flat
and connect them out
the back with ribbon cables.
The metal connections
will touch the case
and each other
- and short everything out.
- We could put cardboard
between.
Well, then we'll
have a cooling problem,
if we can even fit the fan.
Unless we don't
even use a fan.
Yeah, we just turn it on
before he gets here
and kick him out
before it melts.
Or you could just
take your time,
do it for real.
Well, we don't have
that kind of time
at $5 an hour.
So it's about price,
it's not about Joe.
No, it's about both.
It's about not letting him
dictate our vision.
But couldn't this make
Mutiny better, these things
that he wants?
All right,
I'll leave you to it.
Ah.
You always were
the prodigy.
Mm, not with
transmissions.
You always kicked
my ass at those.
( groans )
You think that stuff
made you sick?
Maybe, but that
time in the shop made me
an engineer, you know?
Guts in a machine equals
guts in a machine.
You know, I bet Dad wishes
you had stayed behind
to run the shop.
Hey, why don't I borrow
your truck tomorrow?
I'll head up
to Sacramento,
talk to Dad?
- Yeah.
- Hmm?
Yeah, of course.
Yeah.
Um, I should warn you,
though, that some--
some jag-off backed into it
a week or so ago
and so there's
just one headlight.
I know.
I'll be careful.
- It's really good
to see you, brother.
- Yeah.
( engine stops )
Hey, thanks
for meeting me.
Not a problem.
So where you wanna
have this talk?
Hop in.
- ( bird screeching )
- Gordon: So, how often
during the work week?
Well, a little less
since that bar fight,
but probably still
three, four days,
often before noon.
- Does Wendy know?
- Oh, she knows.
And the truck?
He stayed
till after close
a couple weeks ago.
Next day,
he said he swerved
to avoid a deer.
Yeah, I called my dad.
Although, it was a rabbit
when he heard that story.
- ( Gordon exhales )
- ( sighs )
So, anyway,
that's the boring-ass story
of your alcoholic brother.
If you've heard enough,
I think I'll get home
to my kid,
stop narcing on
my high school boyfriend.
( chuckles )
Hell, I got weed
in my purse right now.
- Call myself a mother.
- ( laughs )
( sighs )
What?
I'm sure you're
a great mother.
I was also thinking
how great weed sounds
to me right now.
Tom:
The external modem
is not gonna fit.
The box, it's big enough,
but it's not tall enough, okay?
The L clips
on the 64 serial port,
they're too high.
We had to hacksaw
them down.
Yeah, but an external modem
will give it away.
We can't...
Could we fake
an online connection?
Have Joe
dial into the network,
but he's actually just linked
to another Commodore
in the house?
- I have completely
corrupted you.
- That's a great idea.
But what cable's
gonna be fast enough
and also not completely
give it away by being
out in the open?
( Donna hisses, sighs )
Wait, what if we--
Carl, did you guys
ever get the HBO working?
Uh, kind of.
Like, we watched
"Cat People" the other night.
You could see
about half a boob,
which we--
Oh, my God!
The coax.
- Lev: Yes.
- 10BROAD36.
We can use
Ethernet encoding.
Plus-- plus, the cable's
already hidden along
the walls.
We can just adjust it
where we need to.
We'll still need
to hear a modem, though.
- Bodie?
- Yeah?
Do you still have
that little recorder?
Okay, go record
the modem connecting.
Then we'll pull out
the recorder's power switch,
we'll run wires up it,
- stash the whole thing
in the AT&amp;T--
- Someone pinches the wires
- and then it triggers
the recording.
- Bodie: On it.
- Okay, how much time
do you need for the coax?
- Two hours, tops.
Gordon: Oh-- oh, my God,
I was so paranoid after
that first experience.
I think I stopped
getting high till college.
( laughs )
And then you
made up for it.
I totally made up for it.
It was Berkeley.
Yeah, yeah, you were
always the smart one.
If I was so smart,
why'd you go out
with Henry?
I was 16.
He was the cute one.
- Oh, jeez!
- ( laughs )
He was never
as funny as you.
Henry could
catch a pass,
but you always
had us cracking up
in the stands.
Jesus.
What?
It's just been
a long time
since anyone's thought
of me as being funny.
You know,
it's so interesting
who we grow up to be.
Have you ever thought about
who you could've been
if you'd have taken
a different path?
Sure.
So, what are you saying,
you should've done
something else?
Stayed here?
Sold tractors off the 5?
You got nothing
to complain about.
Yeah.
God, it feel so good
to just sit here
and do the wrong thing
with you.
( lighter clicks )
Well, I don't
want to keep you.
I'm sure you got better
things to do than sit
in the back of a truck
and just listen
to me babble on.
Yeah, actually I do.
I'm having
a good time.
Okay, log on.
( keyboard clicking )
( modem dialing, ringing )
( modem beeps )
( modem screeching )
( keyboard clicking )
Not bad.
Yeah,
for monochrome.
- Go ahead, play something.
- Whoa, hang on.
I wanna--
I wanna see mail.
Uh, so it's inside the game,
so select what you wanna play.
- Uh-huh.
- Okay, and now find Lev
on the user list.
I'm NewWaveLev.
Okay, then hit Alt+M.
( keys clack )
- Donna: Mm.
- This is still Community.
Exactly.
We built the mail client
on top of the existing code.
So if a user is online,
they get the message instantly,
and if they're offline--
Lev, sign off--
and, "What hath
God wrought?"
Okay, now, Lev,
sign back on.
( computer beeps )
Now.
That's very clever.
Okay, so,
that's everything
you asked for.
Looks like it.
Wait, wait, wait.
I've got a game open.
I want to play it.
Yeah, go-- play it.
Go ahead.
( beeping )
Hmm.
Here, try something else.
There's--
No, I want
to play chess again.
( beeping )
- What about--
- One more time.
( beeping )
Hmm.
I find it remarkable
that three different
human Mutiny users
opened with the same
King's Indian defense.
It's almost as if
they were programmed
to do so.
Oh.
Your computer is melting
to the table.
Here.
- ( grunting )
- ( computer case creaking )
Interesting.
I've never seen a Commodore
like this before.
Must be
an exclusive model.
And look...
there's no modem.
We're not even online.
UNIX.
You couldn't do it.
Oh, it's not that
we couldn't do it,
we just thought
it was a waste of time.
But you did have time
to animate the games,
gut the box,
fake the data.
How are you
streaming it?
- Joe?
- What? What do you want?
You want to insult me again,
say I'm a bad guy,
a bait and switch artist?
I put you on the network.
I handed you a deal
my boss didn't want
you to have.
Don't do this
to me again.
You did this
to yourself.
What kills me about it
is you're so much
better than this.
( engine starts )
( screams )
( door opens )
( footsteps approaching )
I have to tell you
something.
Well, this night
took a turn.
- Hey.
- What?
Can I be honest
with you?
Gordon, I'm a big girl.
I know what this is.
There's something
wrong with me.
Tell me something
I don't know.
No, there's something
wrong with me.
It's in my brain.
I've had problems
with my hands
and my speech.
I may not ever
be the same.
I mean, it may
even get worse.
Gordon, I'm sorry.
- I--
- I'm scared.
Like, I'm really scared.
It's okay.
I mean, it's okay
to be scared.
I'd probably
be scared, too.
Part of me
wanted to believe
that if
I didn't say anything,
it wouldn't be real.
But the weight of it...
I understand.
You can't imagine
what it's been like.
I mean,
what does this mean?
- You know,
what about my kids?
- Gordon, I--
Am I gonna wake up one day
and not feel my legs?
Are they gonna have
to put me in a home?
I mean, Jesus, Jules,
I could die.
And I haven't even
told my wife.
- What?
- I can't, her job.
I've been carrying
this all alone.
Okay, stop.
Stop.
Gordon, what are you
doing right now?
Nothing.
We're just talking.
No, no, you're dumping
all this on me.
- Wait, what?
- Wait, is that
what this is?
Is that why
you brought me
out here?
- So you could
unburden yourself?
- No.
Look, if you wanted
someone to talk to...
- Wait, Jules.
- Oh, my God.
I'm grateful to you.
- Grateful?
- Yeah.
( scoffs )
Jules.
( turns engine off )
You know, Donna,
Mutiny might be done.
I mean, we might not
exist tomorrow.
So if you're doing this
for the company...
That's not why
I'm doing this.
Do you want me
to come with you?
It's all right.
Thanks.
Yeah.
( crying )
Look, I don't know, Dad.
Hey, what happened?
You okay?
- Where were you?
- Come here.
Henry:
She woke up and didn't
know where you were.
I tried Dad,
but I guess you
didn't make it.
Yeah, I had to stop
and talk to Jules
about a few things.
- You kidding me?
- Wendy: Henry.
Yeah, like hell
you were just talking.
( sniffs )
Yeah, you smell like weed
and you also smell like--
Henry!
What is going on?
What's going on is
my brother's a selfish prick
and he always has been.
Hey, get ahold
of yourself.
I thought you were driving up
to talk to Dad to help me out.
I did talk to Dad
on the phone before
I went to Duffy's.
He said that you leveraged
the shop into the ground
over the past three years
and pissed away half
the customers.
- That's bullshit!
- Look, he's worried
about you, Henry.
- I'm worried about you.
- Okay, so let me get this
straight.
So you-- you bang
my ex-girlfriend,
cheated on your wife
because I drink too much?
Listen to me,
we were just talking.
Now you're lying
to my face!
You can't stay
here tonight.
Hey, listen, Henry,
the whole reason
that I flew out here--
Please,
just leave, Gordon.
- Just go.
- ( Haley crying ) Daddy.
Oh, come here, sweetie.
Come here.
( phone ringing )
Girls on answering machine:
You've reached the Clarks!
- Gordon.
- Donna.
- Joanie.
- Haley.
All:
Leave a message.
- ( beeps )
- Gordon: Donna,
are you there?
- ( Haley crying ) Mommy.
- Haley, it's okay.
It's okay.
Gordon:
Honey, it's me.
Pick up the phone.
Hi, I'm here.
Is everything okay?
No, it's Haley.
She woke up.
There's some
bedtime thing you do.
- She said it'd help if--
- Yeah, yeah, of course.
It's...
Does she have Jinx?
Yeah, she's lying down
with him now.
Okay, put the phone
on the pillow next to her.
Hey, come here.
Come here.
Hey, hey, baby girl.
You okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
You listen really
carefully now,
all right?
Mm-hmm.
♪ Haley, mine,
don't you cry ♪
♪ Haley mine,
dry your eyes ♪
♪ Rest your head
close to my heart ♪
♪ Never to part,
baby of mine. ♪
( humming )
( humming continues )
Two days ago
you told me that I was
the building manager
and that our involvement
with our network partners
ended at the rent
we charged them.
I disagreed,
so this is what I did.
I gave Mutiny
a very specific
set of benchmarks,
goals I wanted
them to achieve
in exchange
for a reduced network
rate of $3.50 an hour.
- The floor you specified.
- I'm sure you did.
This is beginning to feel
like a pattern, Joe.
- How am I supposed
to trust you if every--
- Here's what happened.
They completed
the first two
in 24 hours.
The third they deemed
a waste of their time,
but they didn't
tell me that to my face.
Instead, they decided
to try and deceive me.
Now you know
how it feels.
Here's the interesting part.
Just to avoid doing it,
they ended up using
a sophisticated
Ethernet encode
and streaming data
over line they were using
to steal pay television.
The technology
is called broadband.
So new it's only being
used in a couple college
campuses and military bases.
Commercially it's too
expensive and there's not
nearly enough line laid, but...
- But?
- 10 years from now,
it'll likely make
modems irrelevant.
These kids rigged it up
on their own in a day.
So what's
your point, Joe?
I think we should
acquire them.
( theme music playing )