( clock ticking )
- ( high-frequency ringing )
- ( Gordon's voice echoing )
I spoke with a doctor.
And he's a really,
really good doctor.
And he assured me
this is not something
to worry about.
( Gordon's voice )
This is not a death sentence.
I'm okay.
This is a complication,
that's it.
Lord knows
we've overcome our fair
share of those, right?
Yeah. I can--
I can leave work.
I can quit and stay
and make sure you're
all right.
Donna, this cannot,
will not derail anything.
Your work-- everything
that you're doing.
That would break my heart.
I feel fine.
Yes, my hands
are a little weak,
and, yes, there are
small things, tiny things
here and there,
but I feel good, okay?
I'm gonna live my life.
I'm moving forward
with the company.
Gordon, how?
My office is 23 steps
from the bedroom.
There's no driving,
no commute,
my engineers are
my most trusted friends.
And worst-case scenario,
you're here.
We're gonna
be okay, okay?
I'm sorry you felt
like you couldn't tell me.
I was-- I was scared.
I didn't know.
I'm here now, okay?
I'm here.
Wait, wait.
No, it's okay.
Um, can we just, uh...
Yeah. Yeah.
Let's just...
Jacob:
What do you think about 10,000
square feet of office space?
We'll do it gratis
and off-site.
Nowhere near the stench
of the oil business.
I think they'll love it.
- They'll never have to
see a suit and tie.
- ( both chuckle )
Do you have the zoning records
on Mutiny's current address?
Just to take that further
for a second,
where they are now,
east side, neighborhood's
a little rough,
house itself hasn't seen
a coat of paint since the
invention of the Model A,
but the heart of the company
is sewn up into its walls.
We could save some coin
and embrace that motley
spirit.
There's nothing stopping us
from buying up the house,
the entire block.
We could turn the place
into a mini campus.
Let them design it,
grow it as they see fit.
Change as little
as possible.
Then they could
pepper the place
with foosball tables
and arcade cabinets.
( chuckles )
That would certainly
win more votes
than our 401(k)
and platinum dental.
Drop in a grid
of IBM 4361 Superminis,
300 dedicated
phone lines,
give them
direct admin access
to the mainframe,
I think we got 'em.
That's brilliant.
Great work, Joe.
Give 'em a call.
Let's get this thing done.
Three bucks and
my Doctor Doom says
red all the way.
I'll bet Kang on blue.
Kang?
Dude, everyone has Kang.
I have five Kangs.
Arki has 11 Kangs.
Kang is like
the John Q. Public
of action figures.
Fine,
my black Spider-Man.
- Yeah!
- Oh!
All:
One, two, three.
( cheering )
Guys!
Whoa, why is no one working?
- Is something wrong
with the network?
- Bodie: Not yet.
Unless Joe MacMillan's
morning coffee tastes bad.
- ( scoffs )
- Okay, well, shh.
( music playing
in background )
Hi, sorry about that.
Oh, please, I raised
three rambunctious boys.
The place
feels like home.
( chuckles )
What was Tom like
as a kid?
- Oh, God.
- I'll try not
to embarrass him too much.
Oh, you say that
10 minutes after
telling her about
the time that I wet
your bed.
But little Tommy
was the golden child,
even if he was
more of an indoor boy
than his brothers.
Every day after school,
he got a cupcake and a Kayo
just for keeping me company.
- Oh, spoiled.
- Mother: Always.
Oh, I gotta get
to the depot.
Yeah, okay.
Oh, yeah.
Cameron, thank you
so much for lunch.
It was great
meeting you.
No, it was great
to meet you.
I haven't seen Tom
this happy in a while.
Thank you for giving him
such a wonderful
opportunity here.
We're glad to have him.
This is a very, very
special place.
And I know
you're bound to have
tremendous success.
Thanks.
- Bye, baby.
- Okay, I'll see you at home.
- Bye.
- All right. Okay.
Um, chicken parmesan,
is that okay?
And he can cook, too.
- Can you beat that?
- No.
Okay.
- Mother: Bye.
- Bye.
( exhales )
Little Tommy.
Thank you.
I know she can
be intense.
I liked meeting her.
( phone ringing )
Mutiny.
- Cameron, it's Joe.
- Who is it?
Westgroup
wants to buy you.
Is it him?
Is he cutting us off?
I'm coming over with
an official acquisition
offer tomorrow.
Cameron?
Cameron,
this is good news.
I swear.
( theme music playing )
( music playing
in background )
( door opens, closes )
Hey.
Okay, Joe's gonna
be here any minute.
So, I'm thinking that
we'll listen to him,
hear him out,
and then act professional
and then just let him
down easy, right?
- I'm gonna need
some time off.
- Now?
Starting after the meeting,
a few days, at least.
Is everything okay?
It's, uh--
( knock on door )
We ready to talk?
Jesus.
- So that's it, huh?
- No.
Those are just
the numbers.
Here are some others.
Inventory:
31 Commodore 64 machines,
each with a 1541
peripheral floppy,
12 recently purchased
ST-412 10-meg hard drives
for backup,
22 employees burning on average
3,000 kilowatt hours per month,
1,284 paying subscribers,
and one coffee machine
using Maxwell filters.
My point is, you don't
care about numbers.
You shouldn't.
What makes this place special
is people sharing recipes,
advice,
human experiences,
connection
over the speed
of a phone line.
Mutiny's killer app
isn't games, it's people.
And when you sign with us,
you won't have to worry
about numbers anymore.
You can let us
handle that part
so you can focus
on what you love,
which is bringing
people together.
- We're not interested
in minimizing games.
- Neither am I.
Games are the innovative
lifeblood of this company.
Vital for technological
breakthrough.
Essential for bringing
users into the door.
But once they've arrived,
connection trumps content.
Starting day one,
Westgroup will begin
a global expansion
of your network.
That means reaching
thousands and thousands
of isolated users
all over the world
and suddenly making them
feel less alone.
Uh, just
to talk specifics,
what exactly would
global expansion look like?
- We're not interested.
- ( sighs )
I think-- I think
we should take a minute
with this.
- I have.
- Donna: Maybe I'm crazy,
but it sounds to me
like Westgroup
wants the exact same
things that we do.
I'm not sold yet
either,
but I think
we should hear this out.
Joe:
Let's leave the past
where it is
and build something
truly special together.
No, scratch that.
You build it.
I'll get
out of the way
this time.
You'll get
out of the way?
Hey!
Everybody, listen up.
- Cameron, come on.
- Here's what's going on.
Joe MacMillan
and Westgroup Energy
want to buy us up.
You hear that?
Yeah.
We can all go work
for a bunch of oil
company suits downtown.
- How's that sound
to you guys?
- Boo.
Oh, what, does it sound
like selling out?
- Yeah.
- 'Cause that's what
it sounds like to me.
Yeah, instead of building
kick-ass games,
they want to turn this
into a place
- where housewives
can share their recipes.
- Coder: That's bullshit!
What?
Oh, wait, you don't want
to wear a tie to work?
You don't want
to clock in and out?
- No. Hell, no.
- So you'd rather
be equal partners
in a thing
that you created
with your own blood
and sweat and tears
than mindless stooges
in a corporate food chain?
- Coders: Yeah!
- ( clapping )
( chanting )
Mutiny! Mutiny! Mutiny!
- ( coders cheering )
- ( chanting continues )
( coders cheering )
( chanting continues )
- Coder: Great! All right.
- Coder #2: Let's do it!
( chanting continues )
All right, first off,
I wanna thank you guys
for knocking off
a few days' vacation time
so we can try this thing out,
all right?
I'm not asking
for full buy-in now.
I believe the proof
is in the pudding.
Once those days are up,
if you want in, you're in.
- Yeah?
- Tandy, EDS,
General Dynamics, Sabre.
That's a lot of salary
to walk away from after
a couple weeks.
Yeah, yeah.
I know it is.
And that's why tomorrow
I want each of you
to bring in your most recent
pay stub so I can match 'em
in good faith.
Look, I'm not handing out
parking spaces
and gold watches just yet
because it's just us, okay?
100% fulfillment.
Guys with screwdrivers
and soldering irons
sitting at these benches,
doing what they do best.
Once we get going,
I'm dropping ads
in the biggest national
computer magazines.
No more retail store
middlemen,
no more cubicles,
no more bullshit,
all right?
Just these and this.
- ( chuckles )
Paging Joe MacMillan.
- ( all chuckle )
We'll standardize around
the Intel 186 '87 processor
running at 8 MHz.
10-meg hard drive,
5 1/4 floppy.
Eventually,
we'll go to 12 MHz
on the 286-based system,
but for now I want
to stick with the 186
so we can keep prices down.
How far down, you ask?
800 bucks per unit,
give or take.
All depending
on what options
the customer chooses.
They want a standard
Lincoln Town Car, boom.
They want a Ferrari?
Hey, they got the money,
honey, we got the time.
A nimble economy job,
500 out the door.
Prices are lower
than retail brands
across the board.
We're offering the customer
unlimited self-assembly
with the convenience
of plugging it in
and flipping
a switch.
Open architecture, baby.
The destiny
of every box we build
lays in the hands of the user
turning that mother on.
So, what do you say?
You guys want to slam
one of these together or what?
It's not a death sentence,
it's a complication.
And Lord knows the two of us
have overcome our fair share
of those.
What?
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm still on "brain damage."
Microscopic.
Some mild effects.
- Like what?
- Like muscle weakness,
some memory lapses.
He might seem a little off
once in a while.
Like when he dug a hole
in your yard in the middle
of the night?
No, no,
that was work, stress.
What about
when Gordon flew out here
all those years ago
to ask your father's
permission to marry you?
- What happened?
- No, Mom-- now you're
being ridiculous.
- What happened, Donna?
- Mom.
He was so nervous
that he got on
the wrong plane.
Ended up in
Salt Lake City.
Had to call your father,
who ended up booking him
a seat.
Even told the gate agent
to make sure he got on
the right flight.
That's not--
that's-- it's cute.
It's-- that's--
Jesus, Mom, that's one
of my favorite stories
about Gordon.
That has nothing
to do with this.
What if he gets worse?
What if one day he's
in a wheelchair?
What then?
Well, then we will
deal with it.
What if something happens
when he's taking care
of the girls, honey?
- Have you thought of that?
- ( groans )
I know it's hard,
but you have to.
Maybe what happened--
the baby--
was a blessing
in disguise.
Hey, how's it
going over here?
Whatever, whatever.
What, when are you
gonna meet up with
this guy?
- George, right?
- I don't know.
We talked about doing
something tomorrow,
but maybe never.
- Lev, do it.
Stop being such a wuss.
- ( laughs )
Shut up.
You still owe me
a black Spider-Man.
- ( laughs )
- Hey.
I think I got it.
Coder:
All right, let's go.
Where's how much
it was for?
I haven't found it yet,
but look.
Office space renovation
and expansion,
- something-something--
- Cameron owns 90%
of this place?
Founding
entry-level employees
entitled to a 64% increase
of current salary
and 1% of sale price.
( speaks Russian )
1% of what?
Well, we already said no,
so it's 1% of jack shit.
Let's be clear.
You didn't bring me here.
I elected to show up.
Everything you say in this room
goes right back to Cameron.
And I have every expectation
that Cameron knows you came
to see me.
You know this is
a good deal.
The terms are not insulting,
yeah, but it ain't my company.
Can't fault the kid
for being a little squirrely,
either, can you?
Hell, Joe, you seemed like
a pretty good deal to me
back in the day.
I never asked you
to embezzle that money, John.
- ( scoffs )
- If you hadn't taken matters
into your own hands
and instead
just listened to me,
you'd be a multimillionaire
along with Nathan right now.
I know you see it.
You always have.
You went to bat for the Giant
because you believed in it.
You're at Mutiny
because you believe
in what they're doing now.
I'm at Mutiny because
I'm a 55-year-old ex-con
who can't get a job.
You're an extremely
valuable asset.
Please, Joe.
I can't take
such a large amount
of sunshine up my ass.
It makes me itch.
We're going to need
to pitch this program
to nine different
global subsidiaries.
That's gonna require
serious sales acumen.
We want you on that team.
We?
Man, you're
not pitching shit
unless she miraculously
changes her mind,
and I work out of her kitchen
until the day she says
otherwise.
You belong
in a corner office
and we've got one
waiting for you right here.
( sighs )
You have Cameron's ear.
She can hate me
all she wants,
but don't let her
cut off her nose
to spite her face.
I know you're
her go-to.
It ain't me, babe.
Is it Donna, then?
What can I say?
The kid's in love.
- ( knock on door )
- Oh, Jacob.
So glad you
could swing by.
- John Bosworth.
- Hey.
- I've been hearing about you
in my circles for years.
- Sure.
I'm really looking forward
to having someone
of your background
and experience on this team.
I'm sure we both
can learn a thing or two
from each other,
don't you think?
Oh, I think so.
I think so.
- Thank you.
- Look, I'm sorry to be
in and out like this.
I have to be
in Houston by 4:00,
but when I heard
that you were coming in,
- I just had to come over and
introduce myself personally.
- Oh, sure, sure.
- It's a real pleasure.
- Pleasure's mine, Jacob, yeah.
( chuckles )
Joe.
You know...
you're not gonna find
a deal like this
anywhere else.
You might be right.
But I won't
be bought, Joe.
And if that's
what Cameron wants,
none of us will.
But we can offer an option
for a micro 3 1/2.
- Single or double-sided?
- ( generator whirring )
Offer both,
but double costs more.
Hey, you don't have to
hang out here all day,
you know.
Look, you've been living
with this for a while.
I haven't.
But, look,
it's more than that.
I've been gone too long.
I've missed you.
I've missed you, too.
Hey.
- I know that's why
you went to Henry's.
- What?
You needed someone else
because I wasn't there
for you.
Well, you're here now.
- Hey, Gordon?
- Yeah?
- Where do you keep the mugs?
- Left of the sink.
Want me to make you
a new pot?
Oh, it's actually
for smaller screws.
Tiny, tiny stuff.
- How's everything
going out there?
- Great.
Laying out
the prototype specs,
digging in on mods.
How's Gordon
handling everything?
He just bought 40 grand
worth of CPU chips
over the damn phone,
so I'd say pretty good.
- $40,000?
- Yeah.
Does that
seem okay to you?
Why, is something wrong?
No, no, nothing.
Just, could you keep
an eye on him
and let me know
if he seems...
different,
you know, or...
Sure, will do.
Larry, what's the holdup?
You puttin' the moves
on my wife?
- ( chuckles )
- Uh, no, sir.
Gordon:
We got work to do.
( elevator bell dings )
- You went to my house?
- I thought I'd try you there.
You weren't home,
so I left the--
The terms sheet, yeah.
You knew I'd be at work.
Do you know who was
at my house?
My mother.
Do you know she cried
when she thought
I was getting this kind
of a payout from the sale?
And then she cried again
when I had to tell her
that it wasn't true.
Do you--
do you understand
the recklessness
of telling
those kinds of lies
to someone like that?
Who's lying?
These numbers are real.
That's the same
acquisition offer
tendered to Cameron
and the senior staff.
The only new piece
of accounting here
is what you would
personally stand to make.
- A bribe, you mean.
- I just did the math for you.
You know, Tom,
you could've told me
all this over the phone.
And yet you're here.
You invaded my space,
I figured I'd invade yours.
Mm.
You care about Cameron.
You should.
She's special.
But you have to ask yourself
if you're doing right by her
if you let her make
this decision from a place
of pure emotion.
I'm not even gonna
tell her that we spoke.
Okay.
( door opens, closes )
That's all
that he told me.
Is that
what you want?
( sighs )
( coders chatting )
( chatter continues )
How much do you
think it was for?
I don't know.
It was five million.
But we already
made our decision,
so let's get back to work
and just forget about it, okay?
No.
You made our decision.
What happened
to democracy?
Maybe your memory's
failing you,
but we all shouted Joe
out of this house.
Didn't we all
make this call?
Yeah, honestly,
we were just curious,
that's all.
- Yeah, it's okay.
Cool, so it's settled.
- Carl: It's fine.
How come you never told us
you own 90% of Mutiny?
You need
to let this go
right now.
How could anything
be up to us at all?
And shouldn't this
be different?
We didn't know
the details of the deal
or that we were turning
our backs on $5 million.
What?
What do you want?
A vote.
A real vote.
Fine.
Yes, fine.
We'll have a vote.
For you, so that we
can put this to bed.
Everyone come in here.
I'll call your names.
Raise your hands if you
want to sell, okay?
Sell.
Yes, got it.
Arki.
Sell.
Carl?
Can I abstain?
Okay, not sell.
Wonderboy.
Not sell.
Bosworth.
( sighs )
Well?
Not sell.
( phone ringing )
Tom?
Bosworth:
Mutiny.
Cameron:
Tom?
Jesus.
Cameron.
Cameron!
Lev's in the hospital.
- ( music playing
in background )
- ( chatter )
What are you
waiting for?
I know my father
has this idea of me
as some damaged little girl
unable to keep a relationship.
I'm not exactly
eager to prove him right.
- Then don't.
- Oh, please, don't make this
harder than it already is.
( sighs )
This is a scintillating
conversation.
Dad, uh, Joe and I--
well, I haven't been
exactly happy in Dallas.
It's been hard
on me, on us,
and last weekend
I was in Austin and
I was thinking that--
No, no, no, no,
I understand.
Things here are new
for both of you.
New job, new home,
new city.
Is it perfect yet?
No, but you're building
a foundation.
- Well, that's not what I mean.
- Well, what I mean is that you
were never very good
at sitting still
for anything.
You know, you don't need
to hit the reset button
every time you feel
the slightest bit
of discomfort.
That's not what I do.
- And if you're
referring to Peter--
- Oh, come on, Sara.
- It's exactly what you do.
- ( scoffs ) Okay.
I do business in nine
different countries,
but compared to you, I feel
like a thousand-year-old
oak tree.
You've finally found
a guy you can trust,
someone who can help you
heal those old wounds.
Frankly, I'm delighted
that you're with Joe.
Even right now,
you seem much more
grounded to me.
Look, I hate to see
both of you
throw away everything
you've been building here
just because of some
anxious whimsy on your part
stemming from the mistakes
you made with your ex-husband.
With all due respect,
Jacob, I don't think you know
what you're talking about.
- Ah.
- Sara deserves a little more
credit than that.
She sees the best in people.
That's not a weakness,
it's her strength.
I'm sorry.
You think you
know my daughter
better than I do?
I think we can navigate
our engagement without
your input.
Does anybody want
to know what I think?
- Gordon: Moment of truth.
- Man: Moment of truth.
All right.
( powers up )
- Geronimo.
- ( men laughing )
- Yeah!
- ( slaps table )
The Giant
took us a year.
The Pro took us
half a year.
We got this sucker
running in two days.
If nothing else,
we're getting a lot faster.
I think pretty soon
we're all gonna be
a whole lot richer.
( all laugh )
You all right, Gordon?
You know, um...
the hardest thing in life
is to get knocked down
and then get back up
constantly.
But we do it
because we love it
and we know deep down
that if it's the right idea,
it could be bigger
than all of us.
For a long time,
I wondered if I was
ever gonna find it.
The closest I've come
is my kids.
Well...
I think I've finally
found something
that will allow me to say
to them with confidence,
"You can do it.
You can follow your dreams.
No matter how hard it is,
you can do it."
Hear, hear.
- Man: Cheers...
- To dreams, Gordon.
Just two weeks ago,
I was ready to walk
into Joe's office
and tell him that a portable
under 15 pounds--
it couldn't be done.
And now the Giant is gonna
be the lightest machine
on the market.
And that is truly
something to be proud of.
Joe as in
Joe MacMillan?
Uh, what?
What about Joe?
Um, anyways, uh...
great--
great work, guys.
( crickets chirping )
( powers down computer )
- ( sirens wailing )
- Woman on P.A.: ...S gurney
to curtain 2.
- EMS gurney
- Hey.
Easy, easy.
He's stable.
It's fine.
He can't talk right now.
He's asleep and they
want him to rest.
What happened?
He was supposed
to go out
with George today
from the network.
Did they get jumped?
There is no George.
It was just
a bunch of guys
pretending to be
a person on Community
so that they could
lure him out and...
Did you give the police
the subscriber info for
the account?
- That should help them--
- No, the address
is phony, so...
of course the dumb pigs
aren't even doing anything
about it, especially--
Um, can I see him?
So, what?
Dinner here
again next week?
We tell him then?
You know, listening
to the two of you
talk in there,
it all crystalized
for me.
This is what's wrong.
You're in Dallas again,
working at Westgroup,
with a network that you
set up in secret--
I think you didn't tell him
'cause you're not ready
to give up on this.
No, when we came down
from the observatory,
we talked about
moving forward,
but the way
you're acting now,
where you're headed,
you're backsliding,
and I didn't sign up
for that.
I don't know what you
want me to do differently.
I want you to stop
meddling in other people's
companies and build your own.
Somewhere else,
like we talked about.
- What are you afraid of?
- I'm not afraid of anything.
You're the one
who's afraid of your history,
my history repeating.
It won't.
I see what I see.
( car approaches )
What was your vote
gonna be?
She told you how
I got a cupcake and a Kayo
every day after school.
What my mom didn't tell you
was that was my dinner.
That way,
she could feed me
for under a buck.
( sighs )
She was laid off
two weeks ago.
But we already
had lunch planned
and she insisted
on wearing her uniform
and I begged her not to.
But she didn't
want you to think...
I don't want you to think
that this is about money.
'Cause it's not.
'Cause my mom
will get by.
We always have.
This job means
a lot to me.
And I hope it goes on
for a long, long time.
But you also mean
a lot to me.
And I want us
to go on
for a long, long
time.
You gave me this job.
It's your company.
No.
This company
belongs to everybody.
I'll call Joe.
I'll tell him
we're selling.
First of many.
Step one,
beef up support staff
of the explosive
Community functions.
Step two,
prep a huge launch
of the latest game,
"Extract &amp; Defend."
Spectacular blitz.
National TV spots,
full-color ads.
Let's hold off
on the games just
for a minute.
Why would we do that?
Three letters-- C-E-S.
The Consumer Electronics Show
is this month,
and from what I hear,
cartridge consoles still
own the games business.
What about Atari?
First company to lose
a billion dollars in a year.
Nintendo.
This, uh,
entertainment system thing
is gonna hit the States
just in time for Christmas,
and the skinny is
that's all she wrote.
Continuing
with online games
at this point
would just be throwing
good money after bad.
You're right.
We should proceed
with caution,
but games are the door.
They get users in.
They get them hooked
on the network.
The better the games,
the bigger the door.
No. Community.
That's the door.
And, in my opinion,
that's everything.
That's what we'll grow.
A big part
of my pitch to them
was that they could
maintain creative freedom.
Yeah.
That was smart.
( faint chatter )
What are you
doing here?
I, um--
I went by the house.
They told me.
We don't know
who did it.
You probably
never will.
Sixth grade,
first day of school.
Someone wrote "fag"
on my locker.
I got some paper towels
from the bathroom,
wet them down,
and scrubbed it off
before anyone could see.
Next day,
they wrote it 20 times
in a permanent marker.
I never went back
to my locker.
Carried
seven textbooks
in my backpack
for the rest
of the year.
I was only 11 years old,
but I was already
running from something.
I guess it made
my legs stronger,
my back stronger.
It's dangerous
to try and really
connect with someone.
It's so special
when you find a person
you can be yourself with.
You were that.
Sara is.
Don't sell.
He'll ruin it.
He won't mean to,
but he will.
He'll make a ton of money,
the company will be
a juggernaut,
but your vision will be
corrupted and lost.
He'll start by pulling
the plug on games.
( groans )
What--
what is this, Joe?
You fight so hard
to get me to sign
the dotted line--
It's not my business.
I'm not gonna
bully you into this.
It's your company.
You should decide
what happens to it.
Maybe you'll make it.
Maybe you won't.
But you'll live or die
by who you really are.
And where do you
fit into all this?
I don't.
I'm removing myself
from the equation.
( sighs )
Donna: Gordon?
What is it?
What's wrong?
Our first order.
Clark Computers.
We're officially
in business.
( laughs )
- ( door closes )
- ( footsteps )
I'm putting in my notice
at Westgroup.
I do believe I'm the person
you fell in love with.
If you want me to go,
I'll go.
Just tell me
what you want.
I want to get married.
( laughs )
( exhales )
That's what we'll do.
No, today.
And in two weeks,
we're in California.
Okay.
( laughs )
- ( door closes )
- ( coders chattering )
Let me just make
one thing clear.
This is my company.
And I'm not selling it.
( music playing )