( keyboard clacking )
"Spinning Round"
playing over headphones
( knock on door )
Joe told me they were gonna
mess with it, with Mutiny.
- And now you decide
to believe him?
- Yeah, I do.
He was telling the truth.
I could tell.
- ( scoffs )
- I just could.
- What, are you mad?
- Yeah, I am.
I wanted to sell.
And I'm not the only one,
by the way.
But you completely
disregarded that
based on some
mysterious feeling you got
off the one person
you told the rest of us
never to trust.
I'm not going
to apologize.
Is that going
to be a problem?
No.
When we're able,
I think we should
find another network.
It's about time we got out
of the Joe MacMillan business.
Yeah, agreed.
( keyboard clacking )
- Jacob: When?
- This morning at City Hall.
We wanted
to tell you first.
Why would you do that?
Don't you think
that's something
I'd wanna know about?
- To be there?
- Well, we wanted it
to be the two of us.
- ( soft laugh )
- No big party, just
two people in love.
- ( sighs )
- Don't be upset, Dad.
This is good news.
I'm happy for you.
It's just...
you're my daughter.
Joe, I'm sure
you can understand
why I'd want to be at
my only daughter's wedding.
Sir, we meant
no disrespect.
You seem to be making a habit
of springing things on people.
We did this together.
It wasn't inflicted on me.
It was my decision,
actually.
Look, why are you
making this about you?
I just told you
I got married.
You should
be happy for me.
I'm sorry.
Congratulations.
To both of you.
Thank you.
Well, if you'll
excuse me for a moment,
I'll go tell Caroline.
Maybe I'll get
a better reaction
out of her.
I take it there's
something else you want
to discuss with me?
- Um...
- Sara can't stand Caroline.
( laughs )
As much as I appreciate
the opportunity you've
given me here,
I think it's time
for me to move on.
Sara and I are moving
to California.
I'm sorry
to lay all this
on you at once.
No, no, no.
You're right.
Maybe it is time
to move on.
No hard feelings.
Best of luck in all
your future endeavors.
Uh, I'm happy to help you
find a replacement.
No, that's okay.
I'll leave that up
to our people.
- They'll find
the right guy.
- Okay.
I can stick around
until you've got
someone in place.
( chuckles )
Don't be silly.
I couldn't give
my daughter a wedding.
The least I can do
is give her a honeymoon.
I'll tell you what.
Ask Caroline for the keys
to my private garage.
There's a '57 Bel Air
convertible in there,
pristine and ready to go.
Take it for
a couple of weeks.
Hit the road.
Uh, I'll talk
to Sara about that.
- Thank you.
- You bet.
I, uh--
sorry the Mutiny deal
didn't go through.
( chuckles )
I've been in this game
long enough to know
things don't always
break my way.
Enjoy the honeymoon.
( floorboard creaks )
( floorboard creaking )
- Psst.
- ( gasps )
- Hey, Gordon.
- Ah! Ah!
What the heck?
Sorry.
( groans )
You okay?
What was it?
It was nothing.
( theme music playing )
- ( chatter )
- ( spray can rattles,
hissing )
Coder:
Hey, how's this look?
Get that ice.
Okay, we did the debugging
of the staircase...
and you reconfigured
the game menu?
Hmm? Yeah, I want
to go over it briefly,
but, yeah, I think
we're basically there.
We are there.
We did it.
It's done.
- It's perfect.
- No. No.
I want to tweak
a few more things
and copy protect it
and maybe rewrite
some of the scroll
at the top.
- It's messy.
- What? Copy protect it?
But we don't do that.
We're Mutiny.
Uh, well, we both wrote
some pretty bitching code.
You want someone
taking that?
I learned to code
by copying other
people's work,
pulling it apart.
So did you.
Yeah, I've also
had my work stolen.
It's not pretty.
We never would've met
if you had copy protected
"Parallax."
Yeah, but we did meet.
So, because we met,
now I can copy protect
our work
without fear
of us not meeting.
Come on, we wrote
this amazing game.
I don't want anyone
taking it from us.
Bosworth:
Hey, Cameron,
you coming or what?
All right, yeah,
everything's squared away.
Okay, kegs
have been delivered,
tables are here,
nitwit's setting up
the PA out back.
You bringing anybody?
Maybe.
We'll see.
This is gonna be
so much fun.
Ugh, it's gonna be
like a hundred awkward
first dates at once.
God, who are these people?
We don't even know.
It's a nice way
to say thank you
for sticking with us
through all the ups and downs.
Which brings us
to our next topic.
Uh, we're doing great.
Community's raking it in.
Hell, we got more and more
users staying on for longer.
( laughs )
Uh, and games?
Well, they're
not growing as fast,
but those users are loyal.
Those boys
ain't goin' anywhere.
Can we afford
to switch networks yet?
Uh, not quite.
Almost.
A few more weeks
like the last couple,
we'll get there.
Okay.
Uh, that's it.
( drums )
Great.
( door opens, closes )
Uh-huh.
- 15 orders today.
- ( doorbell rings )
- Yeah.
- I got it.
How many is that?
Around 250
last I counted.
- 250?
- Yeah, I took out some ads
in some high-end
lifestyle magazines.
I told those dillweeds
they'd wanna stick around.
How are we supposed
to keep up with that
with only two of us left?
Well, we'll hire
some more people.
Company thriving like this,
we can afford some young talent.
- What's that?
- It's a return.
The serial port
wasn't installed
correctly.
No way.
Come on, guys.
Who did this one?
( laughs )
Look who I found.
- Big, bad Stan!
- Howdy, fellas.
- What are you doing here?
- Oh, back in town for a bit.
Thought I'd stop by,
see how you guys are doing.
How's everything
going out West?
What are you working on?
Oh, this and that.
A few things.
Just sort
of germinatin'.
It's great.
There's more VC money
flyin' around
than anyone knows
what to do with.
- How's it going here?
- Oh, great.
Going really great, you know?
A little too great.
So unless you wanna pick up
a screwdriver and pitch in,
we got work we've gotta do.
Okay, well, I'll probably
head over to the Landing
in a little bit
if you guys want
to meet up for lunch.
- Yeah. Sure thing.
- Sounds good.
( snaps fingers )
( Jacob and man chuckling )
Ah, here he is.
Joe, this is Jesse Evans.
Oh, welcome.
It's great to meet you.
You, too, man.
You, too.
Really excited
to be here.
- How was the trip?
- Wonderful, thank you.
Went on our honeymoon
out West, sort of
scouting it out.
Joe is absconding
with my daughter
to California.
Um, started my own thing,
talked to a few VC firms.
That's fantastic.
I'm just coming
from there.
You know Mark Merlis?
Yeah, go back
to my IBM days.
Great guy to talk to.
Knows everybody.
He put me
in touch with Bob Reed
and Stuart Woods.
Amazing.
They're in my pickup
basketball game.
You'll have
to sub in for me
now that I'm here.
You know Jeff Archer?
I'll get you his info.
Great guy,
super smart.
What were you doing
out there?
I started an online
service, Symnet.
Did pretty well.
Eventually got bought
out by Oracle.
Turned that money
into a few different
ventures--
a couple out West,
one in Tokyo.
You know how this business is.
Always gotta be moving
in every direction.
Yeah, sure do.
Really love what you got
going on here, though.
It's a fantastic
opportunity you spotted.
Oh, thank you.
A good friend of mine
did the hardware work,
Gordon Clark.
He's coming by later
to walk you through it.
Great.
Use all the help
I can get in that
department.
Jesse's more
of a big picture guy.
So, what is
the big picture
as you see it?
In Q1, we could be
in four cities--
Dallas, New York,
San Francisco, and London.
By Q4,
we could be in 24.
Positioned around
the globe as we are,
a company this size,
we can arrive on the scene
a major player right away.
None of the uncertainty
of a fledgling outfit.
( Jesse's voice fades )
( phone ringing )
- Hello?
- ( static hissing )
Hello?
- ( quietly ) Jules?
- ( footsteps approach )
( knocks )
Oh, hey.
What's up?
- How was lunch?
- Good, good.
- We brought you a sandwich.
- Oh, thanks. Thanks.
Uh, Gordon, we've been
giving it some thought,
and, um, I think--
it's-- it's not
that we don't believe
in what you're doing here.
No, no.
Heck, no.
But we just
need something
a little less risky.
Need something?
What, you're quitting?
What's the risk?
We got 250 orders
waiting to be filled.
We sure do,
but we're a little old
to be bettin'
our future on this.
So, what?
Stan take you out,
fill your head
with visions of VC money
flowing through the streets?
Oh, no,
that's not it at all.
You know, these fancy
Silicon Valley companies
started out somewhere,
and it's not
in a big corporate office.
It's in a garage
with three guys rolling up
their sleeves,
betting on themselves
and making something great.
Come on, we are
in this together.
You know what?
It's fine.
You know, you guys
are gonna be the ones
on the outside lookin' in.
I'm sure you're right.
But right now I--
I think we've pretty much
made up our minds.
( phone ringing )
You gonna answer that?
( ringing continues )
- Hello?
- Joe: Who's Jules?
- What?
- I called a second ago.
I think the connection
was bad.
Oh, uh, no one.
What do you want?
You were supposed
to be at Westgroup
half an hour ago.
Oh, yeah.
I-- I forgot.
I'll be
right over there.
- ( sighs )
- Sorry, Gordon.
I'm sure you'll
do fine without us.
You guys are
a couple of cowards.
( laughter, chatter )
- Hey!
- ( button clicks )
"East of Eden"
playing in background
The first users
are showing up!
Hi, welcome.
I'm Donna Clark.
You can help yourself
to some food and beer's
over in the hot tub.
- You're Donna Clark.
- Yeah.
I pictured you as fat.
Like, really fat.
Thank you?
Hi there.
( chattering )
Hey, where's
your costume?
I thought we were
going in character,
spy and sentry.
Uh, yeah,
we talked about it,
but I didn't--
Seriously?
Now I look weird.
- ( laughs )
- Well, are you comin'?
I'm-- uh, yeah.
I'm gonna do some work
and finish up,
but I'll be out
in a minute.
- Okay.
- You look good.
Thanks.
It's all standard except
for the custom cabinets.
Connect the PBXs
to the SNA inputs
on the 3090, okay?
It's all here,
but you can give 'em
my number if need be.
Mm, back it up
a little bit.
I need you
to walk him through
what we've done.
I don't have time
for that.
Just give him this,
tell him what I told you,
he'll understand,
all right?
Okay.
Everything
all right?
Yeah, I'm good.
How are you?
How's, uh--?
Sara.
She's great.
Good.
We got married.
What?
( laughs )
Yeah, we spent
the past couple weeks
in California
on our honeymoon.
No kiddin'.
Congratulations.
See you later, Joe.
Yeah.
Think we're
movin' out there,
to California,
so we'll be leaving.
So this might be
good-bye for a while.
Well, hey.
Best of luck.
Yeah, you, too.
Have we landed on the moon?
Of course not.
I mean, you guys have seen
"Last Starfighter," right?
They can do anything
with special effects
these days,
and who has access
to that technology first?
Hollywood?
( laughs )
I don't think so.
"A Spy in the House"
playing in background
James, how are ya?
Okay, so,
this is Mutiny.
Yeah, this is it.
Come on, let me
show you around.
Hey, Bodie.
This is my son
James.
Weird.
Nice to meet you.
Boz has a son.
( laughs )
Come on.
You know,
I tell you, James.
It may not look like much,
but these kids are brilliant.
You would
not believe.
Hey.
- Hey.
- What are you doing?
Why aren't you outside?
Uh, I'm just
finishing up the game.
I'll be out in a minute.
The game is done.
Come on.
This is your company.
Well, I guess
it was stupid to think
I talked you out of it.
Oh, come on.
I'm protecting our work.
- Do you have
any respect for me?
- I respect the shit out of you.
You don't value
my opinion--
- never mind.
- No, Tom. What?
Come on, everyone
is pissed at me in this house
and no one's saying anything.
It's driving me crazy.
What is it?
Okay, it pisses me off
that I told you that
I wanted to sell,
- and then Joe tells you
that you shouldn't...
- Oh, God.
- ...and that you
listened to him.
- You want to sell?
- Tom, they were gonna
ruin this company!
- It's not about--
no, it's not
about the sale.
It's about you and me.
Fine, you know what?
Just break up with me
if you're gonna
break up with me
and we can--
I'm not gonna
break up with you.
I'm just--
I'm just mad at you, okay?
And I can be mad
at you, right?
- So, what, you wanna quit?
- No, I don't want to quit.
I love you.
Why would I quit?
Have you ever had
a disagreement before?
We're just talking.
People talk.
They fight.
They argue.
It happens
every single day.
( exhales )
You love me?
What? N-no-- now you're
putting words in my mouth.
No.
You said those words.
( knock on door )
Hey, there she is,
the big boss, Cameron.
This is my son James.
H-hi.
( laughs )
( phone ringing )
Hello?
Hey, hey, sweetie.
How's camp?
Oh, yeah?
What'd you make?
A rocking horse?
All by yourself?
Did you paint it?
Purple?
Son of a bitch.
No, sorry, sweetheart.
Not you.
That all sounds great,
sweetie.
Look,
Dad's gotta go, okay?
Will you call me
tomorrow?
Okay.
Okay, I love you.
Yeah, Gordon Clark's
got a unique mind.
- Clearly.
This is pretty cool.
- Yeah.
Yeah, if you're
gonna switch over to
a more conventional setup,
maybe it'd be best
if I stuck around
for a few days
to help troubleshoot
with you.
You got
bigger fish to fry.
California's
calling, right?
Yeah.
( chuckles )
You should definitely
bring on a hardware specialist.
The expansion's
gonna require lots
of expertise in that area.
I got it from here.
It's my problem
to worry about.
Thanks for your help.
( door opens )
"Reminds Me"
playing in background
( chatter )
Donna: Lev?
- Lev, you made it!
- Lev: Hey, guys.
- Yo-Yo!
- ( Yo-Yo laughs )
That's funny.
Donna:
You look good, kid.
Hi.
Welcome back.
- I wasn't about
to miss this.
- I know.
Wanted to see
what these freaks
were like in person.
It's really good
to see you.
Lev! You look so fragile.
I want to hug you, but--
Just be careful,
Bodie.
Heard the new game
was pretty cool.
Decided to check it out.
Yeah, I think
you'll dig it.
Thanks for coming.
- Cameron?
- Yeah.
Hey, we're
all here now.
I feel like
it's a good time
to say something.
- Yeah, go ahead.
- No, not me, you.
No, Donna, I really
don't like to do that.
- ( groans ) Okay.
- Go.
( music continues )
- ( music stops )
- ( feedback rings )
Hey.
Hello, hi-- oh, hey.
( laughs )
Hi, hi, everybody.
Uh, I've met
a lot of you already,
but to those
of you I haven't,
I'm Donna Clark.
Thank you all for coming.
And now I would like
to introduce to you
the mind
behind Mutiny,
our leader Cameron Howe!
( cheering )
- All right, Cameron!
- Howe! Howe! Howe!
( laughing )
Hi, I'm Cameron.
Nice start!
- Uh... ( laughs )
- Bosworth: There it is.
Um-- oh, we have
an announcement to make.
Uh, today we're putting
the finishing touches
on our latest game.
It's called
"Extract &amp; Defend."
Yeah!
How many gamers
do we have here today?
- Man: Yes!
- ( scattered applause )
Whoo!
Well, I think you guys
are really gonna love
what we've done, so...
Come on.
Let's grab a beer.
Man:
All right.
- Talk to
your publisher friend?
- Jeanette? Yeah.
I'm gonna meet with her
for coffee once we're
back out there.
How was your last day?
How's the new guy?
Uh, yeah, he's great.
Like him a lot.
Young. Doesn't have
the hardware experience
I would've expected, but...
( pops lips )
seems nice enough.
- You hated him?
- What? No.
Not at all.
Well, there's a palpable
hate energy here.
Oh, I don't know.
I can't put my finger on it.
( sighs )
He seems like
an odd choice
for the job.
You're gonna miss it.
Oh, there'll be
other projects
way more exciting
than trying to take
an oil company
into the future.
Of course, yeah.
Hey, come here.
- ( sighs )
- Come here.
You're a force of nature.
All right?
You make the world
what you want it to be.
It'll happen
in California, too.
H-how about this?
How about we
step out of reality
for the night,
a hard reboot?
I think once you're outside,
you'll realize what's
really important.
How do I get
on the outside?
Well, I found something
when I was cleaning out
the closet.
- What is that?
- MDMA.
From when I was
doing the exposé.
Let's go out tonight.
Let's go to the Starck Club.
We can bid Dallas
a fond farewell.
Show them what
they'll be missing.
- You remember
College Sara?
- Yeah.
- ( laughs )
- I couldn't
keep up with her.
Well, you'd better
do your best.
"Police on My Back"
playing
( music continues )
Hey, you made it!
Thank God!
There's some people here
you really have to meet.
This one guy, he proposed
to his girlfriend after
they met on Community.
- How cool is that?
- That's, uh--
that's great, honey.
Look.
- What? What is this?
- Someone stole my idea.
Oh, well,
your idea is about you.
It's about Gordon Clark.
Computers handmade
by an expert.
Who knows
who these guys are?
All right, look.
The price point's
the same.
I mean, the slogan's
nearly identical.
Gordon, come on.
Let's get a beer.
Let's enjoy the party.
I think it was Stan.
What, Stan, Stan?
I think he got
Ed and Larry involved.
Should I go over there?
I mean, should--
- No.
- Should I say something?
No, I don't think so.
Look, we can-- we should
take a careful look
at this tomorrow.
It's probably
just a coincidence.
Even if it's not,
there's nothing they can do
to hurt Clark Computers
'cause they don't have
the most valuable asset,
right?
Come on, let's go
hang out a little bit.
No.
I think I'd better go home.
I'm feeling a little fried.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, go-- go get
some sleep, then.
Okay.
( mutters )
- Hey, Donna!
Check this out!
- Oh, hey.
( music continues )
Oh. Thanks.
- Cameron Howe?
- Yeah.
Sorry,
you don't know me.
My name is Gretchen.
This is
your company, right?
Uh... yeah.
Yeah, it is.
I just want to say
thank you.
- Um...
- My family's
kind of screwed up.
Well, really screwed up.
I didn't have anyone
to talk to about it
until I found Mutiny.
There are a bunch of people
dealing with the same sort
of stuff and they help me.
They helped me realize that--
that I could walk away.
( voice breaking )
That there wasn't anything
wrong with me.
And I couldn't
have done that
without you.
I'm sorry
if that sounds weird.
No. Oh!
Thank you.
No, it's not at all.
"Why" playing
in background
- ( air hisses )
- ( cheering )
This feels so good!
Oh-ho, really?
Try and keep up.
"Chamber of Hellos"
playing in background
Hey, how's the bride?
Uh...
You gonna pop out
a couple of pups?
Oh, we'll see.
We got time.
It'd sure make
your mom happy.
( laughs )
That's a terrible reason
to have children.
( laughs )
Yes, indeed.
Oh.
Well, James...
- thanks for coming.
- Sure.
Listen, Dad, I know
about this job opening.
It's, uh, an account
manager's position.
And I know you
left Cardiff as a VP,
but it's a solid company.
I know the people.
I could put in
a good word.
We can get you
out of here.
- Thank you, James.
- Yeah.
Okay, all right.
( laughs )
- All right, good night.
- All right, good night, son.
Hey, you've
been avoiding me.
- No, I haven't.
- Yes, you have.
Ever since you said
you love me.
Yes, fine.
I love you.
In fact, I would say
"I love you" is a dramatic
understatement.
I think you're incredible
in pretty much every way.
If it's gonna
be a problem for you,
then I don't know
what to say, because...
it is what it is
and it's not gonna change,
even when you're being
a total pain in the ass,
like you have been
this entire day.
Okay.
( soft laugh )
Just say
the words, okay?
This is gonna be
so much weirder if you
don't just say the words.
- ( groans )
- Hey, hey, hey.
Look at me,
look at me.
Say the words.
No.
( tsks, laughs )
What's-- say the words.
Just say them.
You're terrible.
I take it back.
I take it all back.
( light switch clicks )
Jesus, Gordon?
What the hell
are you doing here?
I know you
stole my idea.
JGL Computers.
Sound familiar?
You had the guys
sabotage me.
The serial ports,
putting my name
on the back of it
just to make
Clark Computers
look like a joke.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Why else
would you come back
from California?
Huh? You gonna use
some of that VC money
to get it started,
you son of a bitch?
I came back because
I was tired of being
laughed out of the room
by a bunch
of 25-year-olds.
- I washed out.
- Well, then, what
the hell are these?
I gotta make ends meet.
I'm doing repairs.
I'm driving around
all day picking up
these busted machines.
Gordon, can I ask?
Are you doing coke again?
What?
No, of course not.
Why would you
even think that?
'Cause you're in my garage
in the middle of the night
accusing me
of stealing from you.
Donna told the guys
to keep an eye on you,
and according to them,
you've been acting
a little nuts.
- Donna told you what?
- I don't know.
But the guys said--
now I'm getting into
the middle of something
- that I don't want to get--
- Told you what?
That-- she said to tell her
if you were acting strange
or, you know,
like the job was taking
a toll on you or something.
She was worried
about you.
Donna?
Unbelievable.
You think she's trying
to shut me down?
God, it's the same thing
all over again.
No, no, no,
you got it all wrong.
She was looking out
for you.
( car doors open )
- You called the cops on me?
- ( garage door opening )
Stan, why would you
call the cops on me?
Because I heard someone
breaking into my house.
Stan, what were you thinking?
Why would you do that?
- Hey, what the hell?
- It's okay.
- That's it, that's it.
- I just want to talk
to my friend
and ask him why
he called the cops on me.
I just wanted to talk--
( grunts )
"Cccant You See"
playing in background
( laughs )
You're amazing.
Amazing.
I feel like there's
a lot of goodness in me,
a lot of greatness,
but I can't get it out of me.
I can't give it to the world.
I have ideas.
I'm not an echo.
I make things in my mind,
but I can't get them
into the world.
I can't get past this.
It's like a trap.
Like the world
won't see the--
me-- the real me.
Oh, no, I see you.
You're
a force of nature.
You're gonna
change the world.
I have ideas.
Online could be more.
It could be more
than just inside bullshit
for anointed
coder shitheads.
It could be universal.
You could live your life there.
It would change everything,
I promise you.
The world we live in now
is going to look like
the Stone Age.
All these people
with their things.
The physical world
is dead.
A pathway
is being built.
A way out, into a world
of pure information.
A shared consciousness.
The future
is bearing down on us
like a freight train
and nobody sees it.
"Boy" playing
in background
Oh.
Is this a good good-bye?
You ready to get
the hell outta Dallas?
I just wanna say
one last good-bye.
- ( air hisses )
- ( cheering )
( laughing )
I kept telling myself
that Mutiny was games,
we are about games.
And I think-- I knew
that if I went outside today
and saw what you'd done
that I wouldn't be able
to tell myself that anymore.
It turns out
I was right.
I just want this place
to be about exploration.
I'm sorry that
I stood in your way.
Thank you.
I'd like to be
a part of it.
You are a part of it.
You built this place.
No, but I mean...
so, on the game side,
we're always pushing
the code, right?
We're trying to get
the most out of it.
But what if we applied
that same pressure
to Community?
I mean,
the functionality
of it could explode.
It could run
faster, smoother
between subjects
or finding certain
users' conversations.
Yeah, yeah,
all of that,
and then also
we could make
the interface
more like
a game's interface,
except not.
But, you know,
it was a world
to navigate
and not a list,
but it was a map,
you know?
( moaning )
- ( grunts )
- ( laughs )
( moans )
This place turns you on?
You have no idea.
( laughs )
- ( men cheering )
- Oh, my God.
( whispering )
Okay, we gotta go.
Come on.
Pants...
( laughing )
I want to see
what's going on.
No, no, no, wait.
They can't see us.
If my father
hears about this,
I'm gonna die.
You go to the limo
and I'll meet you there.
I'm-- I'll be stealthy.
( chatter )
( laughs )
- ( men cheering )
- Man: What's better
than this?
Jesse:
All right,
hey, hey, hey.
( laughs )
Okay.
I just wanted to come down here
to say job well done, guys.
It was a bitch
of an assignment,
but you guys stepped up,
seriously.
- So...
- Man: Oh!
To WestNet!
( men cheering )
( men chattering )
Oh, my God, and then
you could, you know,
walk from topic to topic.
Yeah, and better than that,
you could find other users
at those places.
Yes, okay, I feel like
we have to write this down.
Do we have something--
Carl, could you clear off
the bulletin board?
We need to create
a layout for Community.
I want a list printed
of every room-- Carl.
Carl, what are you
looking at?
I-- I don't know
what I'm looking at.
I logged into Mutiny.
Try to log on
as an administrator.
- ( keyboard clacking )
- ( beeps )
- Uh, I'm locked out.
- What's wrong?
I don't get it.
Where's Mutiny?
We're kicked
off the network.
Replaced by this.
There is no Mutiny.
It's gone.
( cars passing )
Change of plans.
I'd like to make
another stop.
( chatter )
The phone lines terminate
in modem banks at Westgroup.
They switched them over,
so now when you dial in,
the same number you've always
dialed, you get WestNet
instead of Mutiny.
- They've stolen all our users.
- They even cloned our
interface, so most people
don't even know
they're not on Mutiny.
They think we changed the name.
Okay, get on the Community
forums and tell them they're
not on Mutiny.
- What,
they cloned the whole thing?
- Yes, everything, except games.
Yeah, 'cause he realized
Community is where
the money was.
Just tell them to log off
and wait for us to find
another network.
Wait for us?
Oh, Christ.
I mean, why pay
$5 million for us
when they can
just duplicate us
and steal all of our users?
Hello, hi, hi.
This is Tom Rendon
from Mutiny.
Another company's taken over
our network and I just...
No, it looks like us,
but it's not us.
You need to log off.
We'll be up again
in... a week or two?
- Hello-- damn it!
- Hello?
They don't understand.
They're still communicating
with all the same users.
All of their friends
are on WestNet now.
No, no,
this isn't happening!
( chatter )
Joe:
Where's Cameron?
Something's happened
and I need to talk to her.
Where--
where's Cameron?
Where's Cameron?
I got-- I need to talk to her.
Something's wrong.
- Uh, where's--
where's Cameron?
- ( chatter stops )
I came straight here.
I didn't know
about this.
that this was happening.
I had no idea that--
Wheeler shut me out and...
No, I...
I'm-- I'm moving
to California.
I-- I gave my notice
weeks ago.
There's no reason
I would've done this.
I'm on your side.
I wouldn't do this.
I promise you,
It's-- it doesn't
make any sense.
There's this guy,
Jesse-- he did this.
I don't--
I mean, I didn't--
damn it! Uh...
( sighs )
I don't even work there.
I'm going to California.
Cameron, I need you
to hear me.
You need to leave.
No, you don't understand.
Now, Joe.
Gordon:
Why would she
be doing this?
Why would she be doing this?
Why would she
be doing this?
Do you believe him?
Not for a second.
Okay, so what
are we gonna do now?
Cameron, what are
we gonna do now?
( music playing )