( gunshots )
So, we've got about
six grand in the bank.
It's not enough
to fund our own network,
but if we skip
payroll again--
No, we can't.
The coders are burnt.
We have to go back
to them with a plan.
So most of our users
are gonna wake up,
log on,
and wonder
why we changed
our name to WestNet.
Look, I know
you want to strap Joe
to a rail and so do I--
- He's not a priority.
- ( machine whirring )
Okay, so,
all we've really
got at this point
is a house full
of Commodore 64s,
- the XTs, the furniture--
- And our games.
I mean,
that's the only thing
they didn't steal, right?
"Extract &amp; Defend"
is our freshest title.
I think
it can fetch enough
to keep us afloat.
You would do that?
You would sell?
Donna, this is
about survival.
Put out some feelers
to Sierra On-Line,
the cartridge market,
I'll reach out to
the independents.
What about WestNet?
It's too bad we can't
sue 'em.
- ( bullet clatters )
- Your turn.
- ( gunshot )
- ( phone ringing )
Mm.
Yeah?
You gotta be kidding me.
Which-- I mean, where?
( groans )
Yeah, I know the one.
( sighs )
For God's sakes, Gordon,
you can shut up and wait.
- ( groans )
- What does he even want?
A ride home from jail.
- You need anything else?
- Nah, I'll make it.
Thanks.
Go straight home,
Gordon.
Clean yourself up.
Get on that damn plane.
Put all this behind you.
( exhales )
- Hey.
Is it true,
what I just heard?
Uh, probably.
That you're selling
what we've just spent
the last four months
of our lives on?
It's not like I have
much of a choice, Tom.
Okay, can we just--
can we just take it
slow for a second?
( scoffs )
Yes, I really wish
I had that luxury.
I just don't want you
to act too hastily, okay?
Or-- or-- or panic.
Can you--
I know what I'm doing.
Well, at what point
were you gonna tell me?
You know, the guy
who wrote the game.
- Cowrote it.
- Oh, we're splitting
hairs now.
Tom.
I'm tired, okay?
I smell like
gunpowder and beer
and I don't remember
my last shower.
Can you just--
here.
Whoever's still awake,
buy them breakfast, okay?
Tell them everything's
gonna be okay.
I'll take anything
with eggs and--
Green chilies,
yes, sir.
Jesus, can you
just do it?
( theme music playing )
( horns honking )
( car door opens, shuts )
( pounds on door )
Can I help you?
Uh, is this JGL?
Who wants to know?
Uh, I'm Jim Clark.
I was interested
in their work.
( scoffs )
You're late.
Really?
Yeah, they're
out of business.
Cleared out on Friday.
We're hiring, though,
if you're interested.
Lot of late shifts,
but it's steady.
No. Thanks anyway.
All right.
Our lawyers advised us
to sue immediately,
but we're holding off
pending your cooperation.
That number represents
two years of our overhead
plus treble damages.
I only took this meeting
because, as a former client,
I thought you deserved
an explanation.
That's sort of like
a ransom note
after the victim's
already dead.
- I prefer transformed.
- ( scoffs )
Some ideas need
a larger ecosystem.
Give a buffalo
a million acres,
it thrives.
Stick it
on a desert island,
in four generations,
- it's the size of a poodle.
- That's a charming anecdote,
but I work for a living,
so can we move this
along, please?
- We violated no copyrights.
- We own proprietary
algorithms--
You were making
it up as you went,
at least admit it.
Connecting subscribers
in discreet communities--
- The Source does a version
of that-- Delphi, CompuServe.
- Not like us.
Not the same way as us.
This idea belongs
to its originators.
If that were true,
Coca-Cola would still
be a cough syrup.
This community
doesn't like copycats.
We are prepared to reach
out to every trade magazine
in the country,
every reporter
on the tech beat.
Like Leslie Wu Foley
from "PC Magazine"?
Reese Jenkins?
John Krinkey?
Not so close together,
please, guys.
They'll all be sitting here,
right here, in a few hours.
And since
I invited them weeks ago,
I suspect they'll view
your claims as sour grapes.
- We'll do a side-by-side.
- If they can even find Mutiny.
When are you guys
going back up,
by the way?
Look around, Donna.
We're announcing today.
We're all in.
And you're gonna sit there
and tell me, what?
I should've
nobly stepped aside,
watched you guys flop around
for years gasping for air,
shopping your little
regional product
door-to-door
like Thin Mints?
- I'll see you in court.
- Oh, come on.
We both know that's
not gonna happen.
Sorry we couldn't
help each other out.
Holding hands
with Joe MacMillan
never ends well.
Trust me, I know.
What makes you think Joe
had anything to do with this?
You gotta be kidding me.
I think I found
my book idea.
I'm gonna start outlining
it on the plane.
- That's great.
What's it about?
- You.
( laughs )
No, not you individually.
It's more like
the price of adaptation
on modern life.
You know,
transformation, pain.
How many of those pills
have you taken?
( laughs )
No, seriously.
Creative disruption,
you know?
You upset people,
but so does anybody
who rocks the boat.
But you also
gave birth to some
pretty special things.
- ( laughs )
- I'm taking one
for the road.
The movers don't
get here till 3:00.
( knock on door )
Oh.
Joe.
May I?
- Dad.
- Hey, sunshine.
I'm sorry, I'm a mess.
Oh, nonsense.
You look terrific.
( kisses )
I just wanted to wish
the happy couple
bon voyage.
So...
Go West, young man.
Still a wide-open business.
Do well, blaze a trail,
who knows?
Maybe Westgroup will open
an office out there someday.
I have no doubt.
Dad, this is beautiful.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, you're gonna
love it out there.
It's the land
of second chances.
Joe, may I have a word?
- Bye, sweetheart.
- Bye.
You didn't seriously
think that bullshit
would buy my silence?
No.
You're far too
emotional for that.
You stole
intellectual property.
Actually,
I tried to buy it.
A very generous offer,
as I recall.
Only the deal
went south somehow.
No need to dance.
I went behind your back.
I told Mutiny
not to sell and I'm glad.
Every instinct I had
about you was correct,
except how low you'd stoop.
- We're done.
- Are we?
What if I went public?
I'm your son-in-law.
I string together
the right 10 words,
your stock's in the toilet.
You don't
want to do that.
Do you have any idea
how hard it's gonna be
for you to start over?
Without Westgroup,
your resume reads
like a rap sheet.
I'll try my luck.
And Sara? How would
your little stunt
affect her?
There's no upside
to grudges.
Come to our shareholders'
meeting this afternoon.
The day
I vouch for you...
There'll be a lot
of very important
people there.
People who can
make a difference
to your future.
Sara will be delighted.
And we can part friends.
We're not friends.
We're family.
We'll see each other
at Christmas every
other year.
We'll nod to each other
across the room,
and after about
45 minutes of fake
chit chat and eggnog,
I'll make an excuse.
"We have to be somewhere.
I'm so sorry."
And when my children
ask me who that tall gray
stranger in the window is,
I'll remind them,
"That's your grandpa."
I'll see you there.
( engine starts )
- Ahem.
- ( knocks )
Oh, no, it's not
a two-person shooter,
it's a two-perspective
shooter, so it's--
No, we're not compatible
with that platform.
Okay, no, thank you
for your time.
Bye.
Hey, cut that out.
What?
That down-in-the-mouth crap.
Come on, buyers hear defeat,
they scatter quicker
than crawfish
at a church boil.
You're the boss bitch
around here.
Queen of the Nile.
Sittin' on a gold mine.
People be lucky
you don't charge
admission, get me?
You look sharp.
( sighs )
What's that?
Oh, this is...
our next interface.
See these
quick link boxes?
They'll kick users
right over to their
favorite area.
I've already started
coding it.
I'm sorry, did you
want to talk to me
about something?
No, nothing important.
( door opens )
- Sir?
- Oh, yeah, hey.
I'm just, uh,
looking for my car.
Sir, this area
is for employees only.
You can't get in
without a pass.
- Do you have a pass?
- No, I, uh...
Do you remember
what level you were on?
I wasn't really
paying attention.
- Maybe 5F?
- There is no 5F.
This is basement
level west.
Maybe it was an E you saw.
Did you park in 5 East?
Maybe that's it.
Stairwell's
right up there.
Sir?
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
I'm fine, thanks.
Who are these people?
Out of, like,
100 cold calls,
they're the ones
that called back.
Word is they're just
a few weeks old.
Yeah.
So Westgroup
didn't back down?
No, the creep
practically blew his nose
in our settlement offer.
What did Joe say?
He wasn't there.
I don't think Joe
knew about WestNet.
I think maybe he was
telling us the truth.
Okay, we're
ready for you.
Oh, actually, guys,
we're in here today.
( whispers )
Okay, well,
here we go.
Sara:
Maybe you should go.
To the shareholders'
meeting?
Yeah, I mean,
he'd never expect it.
He thinks
you're too proud.
But think about it.
You know, you go there
in front of everyone.
Let them see that
it started with you,
your vision.
Just try and pull
something good out
of this fiasco.
Then we can just
leave it all behind.
Make a clean break.
Look, it's up to you.
I'll be by your side
either way.
Cameron:
So, half the game
is a spy thriller.
Your mission
is to infiltrate
the Soviet prison
and rescue the starving
dissident or...
You're an elite
KGB prison guard.
Your orders--
find and shoot
the American
before he escapes
with your prisoner.
So each level can be played
as either hide or seek.
While totally scrambling
our Cold War preconceptions.
Right, it's like
"Gorky Park" meets
"Red Dawn."
If we can port
the code.
Graphically,
there's no reason
it can't run
off a cartridge.
But without the live
two-player aspect,
- isn't it just
"Battlezone" in a prison?
- No.
No, we like to think
that the tension
and the claustrophobia
really set it apart.
Cool.
It's definitely cool.
Man:
Bryce, a couple
of coffees?
Um, one second, guys.
- I gotta just go that way.
- Oh, sure.
Look, conceptually,
it's really strong.
I just wish we could cover
your development costs.
What you're asking,
it's kind of out
of our price range.
- ( phone rings )
- Well, uh...
Funtime Games.
( speaking Japanese )
Look, I think we should
just get out of here.
Sit tight.
( woman continues
speaking Japanese )
Hey there.
John Bosworth,
Mutiny, Inc.
Bryce, could you
excuse us?
Let's see.
Looks like you're
headquartered up
in Redmond.
What is this?
Distribution network?
- That's confidential.
- That's nationwide, mm-mm.
Gents must have
some serious backers.
Mr. Bosworth,
I'm gonna have
to insist--
Oh, hell, I got no interest
in blowin' your grand plans,
whatever they are.
Yeah, it's a free country.
Couple things, though.
One, well, there ain't
no need to cold-room us
with the toddlers
just to drive down
our price.
Hell, we're
reasonable people.
Two, it's a lot easier
to establish a beachhead
under a friendly flag.
Why do you think Toyota's
building cars in Fremont
rather than Fuji-what-now?
Well, four little words--
Made in the U.S.A.
Your partners,
say they land their product
with strictly
Japanese games--
ones they hire you
to retitle and repackage--
man, that sounds
kind of sneaky, huh?
Kind of like an invasion.
But say they ship
some homegrown titles,
ones they developed
on these shores.
Boy, that's
kumbaya time.
Hands across the ocean.
Might be worth acquiring
for the PR value alone.
Hell, it'll also
make you look smart,
out ahead of the curve.
Hear us out.
You ain't
gonna regret it.
( chuckles )
We sold it.
( cheering )
So, then, what's next?
When do we get paid?
- Who made the purchase?
- How much?
- 50 grand.
- 50 grand?
Enough to hire
a new network
and we will
make payroll.
( cheering )
- ( chanting )
Mutiny! Mutiny!
- What?
- Mutiny! Mutiny!
- Okay, okay, okay.
( chanting continues )
Mutiny! Mutiny!
( thunder rumbling )
( grunts )
( groaning )
( breathes heavily )
( winces )
Jesus.
( panting )
Hello!
( music playing softly )
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Must've been hard, right?
No, actually.
I feel lighter.
I feel clearer
than I've been in a while.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Look, if this company's
gonna survive, it needs
me 100% focused.
- What we've been doing--
- You mean our relationship?
Yeah.
I got too complacent
and happy.
I let my guard down
and it cost us.
Happiness is not
some side effect.
- It's kind of
the whole point.
- Okay.
I'm not blaming you.
I'm taking
responsibility.
I made this happen.
Actually, I think Joe
is making this happen,
and I think you
can't get over it.
Maybe you never have.
You used me.
You made me believe
in what we were doing here.
You know...
you're a lot more like him
than you think.
Do you mind?
( sighs )
( rain pattering )
( chatter )
Need help with that?
It's technical.
( sighs )
Keynote in front
of the board,
that's quite
the wedding gift.
Do me a favor,
get off the stage
before I throw you off.
By the way, a reporter
wants a word with you.
She says she's
an old friend.
I assume you're here
to humiliate me in front
of hundreds of people?
Tempting.
But, no, I guess that's
no longer necessary.
Yeah.
I'm done.
I guess when my life
goes up in a mushroom cloud,
I just naturally assume
you're behind it somehow.
Old habits.
You leaving town?
That's right.
With your fiancée?
Wife, actually.
Going to California
was my idea.
Remember?
( sighs )
At COMDEX.
You almost convinced me.
Someone close to me
said that there must
be a reason
why you're still
a part of my life.
Do you ever wonder?
I mean, what if
instead of chasing
what each of us wanted
separately and obsessively...
we just held on
to each other instead?
( sighs )
I know you didn't
copy our interface.
I know it wasn't
your fault.
I didn't want you to leave
without hearing that.
And...
I must be totally mental,
because part of me
doesn't want you
to go away at all.
You have no idea--
Cameron,
I can't do this.
No.
You're Joe MacMillan.
I think you can do
whatever you want.
Sorry.
Here.
That's what
it could've been.
- One last run-through?
- Yeah, just a sec.
Okay, let's go.
( applause )
Welcome.
It's wonderful
to see you all here.
I hope you all
got a chance
to check out our
communication terminals.
Now you might ask,
"Why is an energy company
messing around
with computers?"
I want to introduce you
to the man who conceived
of our grand strategy,
whose passion convinced
even a stubborn old
fossil like me.
My son-in-law,
Joe MacMillan. Joe?
( applause )
From the cave paintings
to the funny pages,
the stone tablets
to the telephone,
we humans seek,
we crave connection.
The exchange of our
thoughts and ideas
from the trivial
to the sublime.
- ( clicks key )
- Welcome to the
printing press,
the newspaper,
and telephone of tomorrow.
With just a few
keystrokes on a PC,
talk to loved ones
across the country.
Share a stock tip,
a story, tell a joke.
Or, better yet,
find new friends.
People who share
your interests--
music, politics,
movies, sports.
It's a never-ending
conversation on tap 24/7.
No boundaries,
no borders.
It's a pathway
to a new world.
The key, of course,
is the unique interface.
It makes participation
not just fun,
not just exciting,
but addictive.
And all this--
I mean...
all this--
This all began
with a very talented
young programmer
named Cameron Howe.
She saw the future
and she got there first.
I didn't build this.
I don't own it,
and neither
does anyone here.
If we skate past that,
we're doing violence
to the one thing,
maybe the only sacred thing
in our business-- innovation.
Cameron couldn't
be here today,
but her genius
is all around us.
And will be, I suspect,
for years to come.
( crowd murmuring )
Man:
Thank you, Joe.
( whispers )
Thank you.
( lock rattling )
( car door opens )
Hey!
- ( car door closes )
- Hey!
( grunting )
- ( car engine starts )
- Ah!
Hey!
( grunting )
Hey, wait!
Hey, stop!
( grunts )
- Stop!
- ( pounds on truck )
- ( door opens )
( panting )
Paramedic:
Hang on, buddy.
Couldn't fit the rig in here.
The roof's too low.
But we'll get you sorted.
My car.
That-- my car.
That was my car.
That is my-- my car.
( siren wailing )
You want to keep
that ankle stable, okay?
So try not
to move too much.
- ( monitor beeping )
- ( siren wailing )
Gonna be there
before you know it.
( sobbing )
Thank you, everyone.
The truth is, of course,
that we have our own
- dedicated and highly
qualified team...
- Jesse?
- ...working night and day--
- Is this supposed to, uh...
One second.
"She's Lost Control"
playing
Oh.
♪ Confusion in her eyes
that said it all ♪
♪ She's lost control... ♪
We're still working out
some of the--
Jesse, what
the hell's happening?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean,
you don't know?
♪ And she screamed out
kicking on her side ♪
♪ And said
I've lost control again ♪
♪ And seized up on the floor,
I thought she'd die ♪
♪ She said
I've lost control again ♪
♪ She's lost
control again ♪
♪ She's lost control ♪
♪ She's lost
control again ♪
♪ She's lost control... ♪
( music continues )
- ( knock on door )
- Yeah, come in.
- Hey.
Well, how's that
for a day?
( scoffs )
Just pulled it out
of our ass again.
Never gets old.
Yeah.
But we do.
I've been thinkin'.
It might be time for me
to move on outta here.
Yeah.
Wait, what?
- Are you quitting?
- I'm afraid so.
I went for an interview,
and, hell, I guess
they're desperate.
( laughs )
You can't.
We just got back
on our feet. We won.
Yep, and I wish
I could say I was
looking forward
to the next all-night
down-and-dirty scrap,
but I--
what've I got, five years
left of my career?
10, tops?
I gotta get something
stable for my family.
Hell, soon my grandkids.
I'll give you a raise.
It ain't
about the money.
I'm just too damn old
to be eating three meals
a day out of a toaster.
It's undignified.
( laughs )
It's fun.
Well, yeah.
It has been.
Well, what if I don't
accept your resignation?
It'd disappoint me
if you did.
I'll call you tomorrow.
You know, Catherine...
get some sleep, hon.
The next thing you know,
I'm at the bottom
of a stairwell.
So you blacked out?
Maybe,
I don't know.
I just sort of
lost track.
I mean, you know
how I get.
Doc, like
a bad penny, huh?
Can't get rid of me.
( chuckles )
You gonna slap
a cast on this thing,
send me back out
into the wild or what?
Got your juice,
I see.
Yep.
- Just a moment?
- Yeah.
I'm so sorry.
Gordon told me his CTE
was under control.
It is.
We did an MRI last week.
The disease
hasn't progressed.
Then I don't understand.
This episode
was not symptomatic.
It was psychological.
He was dehydrated.
He got lost.
For seven hours,
Donna?
The paramedics said
that he broke down
in the ambulance.
Did he mention that
to you?
A serious diagnosis
can sometimes bring out
underlying problems.
Has Gordon ever
experienced manic behavior
or paranoia
in the past?
Um...
That bad, huh?
So...
I don't think
you're gonna get
to come home tonight.
Dr. Semel thinks,
and I believe him,
that this goes beyond
what we talked about.
- He thinks--
- I know, I know.
I need help.
I was set up.
She sabotaged me.
Christ, can you
even hear your own
rationalizations anymore?
You know,
I'm getting tired
of being second-guessed
and manipulated
and distrusted
when I have
done absolutely
nothing wrong.
Well, why should I
believe a word you say?
Because you're
my goddamn wife!
Ahem.
I don't care about
what you did to my dad.
You two
deserve each other.
It's why you did it.
All this time,
I thought that you
were a victim
of your genius,
some sidetracked prophet...
( voice breaks )
and that I was your
second chance.
But you're not,
are you, Joe?
You're an accident.
You're something
that happens
to people
who deserve better.
I'm not an accident.
I deserve better.
I deserve you.
( sobbing )
I just wish
that you knew what
this felt like.
That you could
just see your face
when you say her name.
Say it, Joe.
Say Cameron.
God, you're lost.
( door opens, closes )
We'll take anything
you can give us--
programming notes,
level layouts.
Yeah, okay, I'll pack
it up and have someone
drop it off tomorrow.
Thanks.
I know it's not easy
letting go of your baby.
Yeah, so what's
your plan?
Did you guys
find a platform
to launch it on?
Yeah, I think we've got
someone in mind.
Probably have to change
the name, though.
"Extract &amp; Defend,"
was that your idea or Tom's?
- What?
- Tom Rendon.
He's so talented.
Tried to poach him
from you guys,
but he said
he'd rather go it alone.
You've seen
his "Parallax" clone, right?
Genius.
Do you know him?
Yeah, we've been
trading hacks for years.
How do you think
we found out about you?
He tipped us off.
Practically broke my arm
till I took the meeting.
- ( rustling on phone )
- Amy: Hello?
Hey.
Why didn't you tell me?
What was there to say?
You already made
your decision.
Wait.
Tom, stop.
Stop!
You'll come back.
You'll wake up
tomorrow morning
and you'll ride
your stupid bike
back here
and I'll make coffee
and you'll pour
your Raisin Bran
and we'll just come up
with something new.
Wait.
I couldn't have done
any of this without you!
No, Cameron.
You did this
all by yourself.
♪ Be my fate ♪
♪ Be my litmus ♪
♪ Be my bones ♪
♪ Be my litmus. ♪