Jesse:
Westgroup headquarters
network
off-line for over 80 hours.
New York's mainframe
off-line for two days.
Hundreds of databases
and disk drives are wiped,
corporate banking
has been frozen
until our accounts data
can be recovered,
legal is drowning
in calls from vendors
and third parties--
Just give me
the damn numbers.
Westgroup stock price
is already down 8%
and we're looking
at an incurred cost
of several million.
And Joe?
The board recognizes
that he's to blame,
but they don't
feel it prudent
to pursue a criminal
investigation.
( chuckles )
So they chose
a scapegoat.
( chuckles )
- They'll be with you shortly.
- My wife, she's not here yet.
Um, I'd like to speak
with her before--
I'll show her in
when she arrives.
Cameron:
So, this is Lev right here.
Donna:
Lev, you look
so cool online.
- Yeah, like in real life.
- ( laughs )
- Cameron: Okay, um...
- Bodie, why do you
have a skull head?
'Cause it's wicked
and awesome.
Yes, okay,
so each visualization
is totally customizable.
The more time you spend online,
the more options become
available to you.
Yeah.
So, walk here to Mutiny Mall,
here to News &amp; Updates--
Is Town Hall ready
for my admin talk tomorrow?
Yeah, you just have
to figure out what you
want to look like online.
Hey, uh, so since
I'm taking over accounting,
I just want to make sure
I have the correct info for
our new network partner.
Is it Telnet or Telenet
with an E?
It's Telenet with an E.
They're based out of DC
and the guy we work with
over there
is Doug or Warren or--
hey, how great is it
we don't even know
his name?
Houston's officially up.
How many
new subscribers?
With the promotion,
I've had 29 sign-ups
with the new 713 number
in the last two hours.
Conquering the world
one area code at a time.
( laughs )
( whispers )
This is so real.
Let me see.
Yeah, is there
something else?
Yeah, uh,
if it's okay with you,
I was wondering
if I can move
to Tom's desk.
You see,
his has two drawers
and mine only has one,
so I was thinking,
"Dave, you bonehead,
you wanna do accounting,
you're gonna need
more than one drawer."
But they don't necessarily
have to be Tom's drawers--
Yes, fine.
Whatever.
Hey, have you, uh,
heard from him?
No.
- Um, how is Gordon?
- Good, good.
I'm gonna go pick him up
from a meeting in a couple
minutes.
- ( ringing )
- Dave: I got it.
Probably Telenet.
- They like to fax.
They're big on faxing.
- ( modem screeching )
Don't worry, I got it.
I was just hoping
to speak with Sara
before signing.
She came in this morning.
I'm sorry, someone
should've told you that.
( sighs )
( music playing
in background )
( scoffs )
You gotta be kidding me.
Donna, look at this.
( scoffs )
Well, we're doing well,
so they're charging us more.
Great, great.
Here we go again.
No, it's because the pie
is getting bigger.
This is just
part of the process.
No, no, no,
this is about being
beholden to somebody else.
I mean, it doesn't matter
if it's Telenet or Westgroup
or Doug or Warren
or Joe MacMillan
or the Pope.
As long as we are on
some other dipshit's network,
this is gonna keep happening.
We'll never be
in the driver's seat.
Well, the only places
that have networkable
hardware
- are big companies...
- I know.
...places that can
afford the metal.
This is time-sharing.
This is the name
of the game.
You know-- look,
we'll counter Telenet,
we'll do the dance.
No, screw the dance.
I want to change
the music.
I know.
Look, I gotta go.
All right,
let's wrap up the day
by looking
at our stress journals.
Last session,
I asked you all
to note your stresses,
big and small,
conflicts,
frustrations, fears,
and rate them from one to five,
five being the most stressful.
First, I'd like
to quickly go around the room
and have everyone say
their final stress tally
out loud.
- Robert?
- 39.
- Paul?
- Uh, 24.
That's excellent, Paul.
- Diane?
- 57.
Why so much stress
this week, Diane?
The bus route changed,
so I've been driving
the girls to school myself
and I had to go by K-Mart,
and the K-Mart by our house
isn't open yet,
so now I have to go
all the way to the one
in Carrollton--
Okay.
We'll discuss that.
- Gordon?
- Uh, ahem, 0.28.
That's pretty low.
Must've been a good week.
Yeah, nothing to report.
I'm home,
taking my medication.
Kids are headed
back to school, so...
What registered
the .28 of stress?
Oh, uh, I couldn't
find my glasses.
Anything else
come to mind?
Something you might've failed
to capture in your journal?
Nope.
Just seeing the glasses
thing here, Brendan.
Okay, well...
since that's all we've got,
that's what we'll workshop.
Why don't you role-play
your stress for us?
Sure.
I woke up
and I thought...
"Where are my glasses?"
And then I found them
and I said...
( chuckles )
"Here they are."
No, let's get you
on your feet.
I'd like to see
you act it out
in the center
of the group.
Here, why don't you
take them off
and I'll hold them
while you look for them?
Okay, it's the morning.
You just woke up,
but can't find
your glasses.
Go.
Oh, no.
I can't find my glasses.
Where are they?
I'm never gonna
be able to see again.
I'm blind.
Oh, no.
Brendan:
Rather than caption
what's happening,
why don't you tell us
how you're feeling?
Right now I feel like
I'm wasting my time.
How do you feel
about losing your glasses?
I'm mad that
I can't find them.
What else?
I'm, uh--
I'm frustrated
and I'm-- I'm worried.
Why are you worried?
Because it's been
a few minutes
and I'm worried
that I lost them
and, I don't know,
I can't remember
where they are,
and is this
just me forgetting
or is this
something more?
Does it scare you
that your illness
might progress?
No.
'Cause they were on
the damn kitchen counter.
( Gordon exhales )
( horn honks )
( sighs )
( theme music playing )
Where
is the peanut butter?
Daddy keeps it up there.
Hmm?
My Eggo's still
cold in the middle.
Well, it's also
drowning in syrup,
so maybe that
makes up for it.
Excuse me!
What kind
of behavior is that?
Why can't
Daddy make breakfast?
You suck at this.
Joanie Marie!
We all need
to work together, okay?
Your dad
got a little upset.
- Like in California?
- Shut up, stupid.
Hey, no name-calling.
What happened
in California?
Nothing.
Joanie?
Daddy and Uncle Henry
got into a yelling fight,
and the three of us had
to sleep in a crummy motel.
Why didn't you tell me
any of this?
Because then you and Daddy
would fight like him
and Uncle Henry.
Oh, what was
the fight about?
Joanie.
Everything okay?
Yeah, uh, Joanie didn't
like her breakfast.
We're out
of orange juice.
And there's no coffee.
( whispers )
It's okay, sweetheart.
- ( phone rings )
- Woman: Reception.
I'll let him know.
Mr. MacMillan,
they're ready.
Bondham:
Yeah, we had
Mutiny in here,
but frankly I was on
the fence about them
from the get-go.
And I heard
they're doing
pretty well recently.
I'm chalking that up
to dumb luck.
Mutiny certainly isn't
the answer to anything,
but I will say
this burgeoning
online sector
is the place to be
in technology right now.
Do you have
something in mind?
Mutiny's fine
if I live in Dallas,
but what if I want
to access information
in Toronto,
San Francisco, Tokyo?
What if I live
in rural Nebraska
where there is no service?
So, what, you want
to do the first online
service in Omaha?
Omaha is just
a place on the map.
I'm trying to make maps
irrelevant.
This service allows
customers to dial in
from one location
and dial out from banks
in a completely different city.
Something like this
sidesteps long-distance fees.
I'm gonna stop you
right there.
Now, you brought Westgroup
into tech recently, right?
WestNet?
All that?
I transitioned Westgroup
into time-sharing
and helped them realize
a dormant passive
income stream.
So why did
you torch it?
- I didn't.
- ( chuckles ) No,
that's not what I heard.
( clicks tongue )
Here's the honest truth.
We don't have
a dime for ya.
We took this meeting
out of morbid curiosity.
Now, the press story
is that Wheeler botched
the tech move,
but I know some guys
on the inside over there
who told me
the real story,
and what I want
to know is...
why?
Also how?
Some destructive program?
Right?
A virus or something?
You know, I looked into you,
what you did at Cardiff.
Immolating 100 computers
out by Lake Texoma.
Holy shit.
( laughs )
I am blown away.
I've never
met a legitimate
psychopath before.
We should buy this.
IBM 3033 mainframe.
It's a refurbish job.
It needs a little love,
but then we'd own it.
- No more network partners.
- Cameron...
You know where
I found this?
Community.
I went into
the Tech Talk room,
I wrote out the specs
we'd need,
and suddenly I had
100 Mutiny field agents
on it.
They found this thing
in two days.
This machine
is 10 years old.
It uses tape drives--
- Which we--
- Control unit is missing.
And even if it wasn't
in Daly City, California,
this is all
of our liquid cash
plus most
of our projected income
for the next year,
and that's before shipping.
And even if we could
get it on a truck to
move it out here,
where would we put it?
Yes, there
are challenges, sure,
but we need
to start moving in a--
If you want to drive
a submarine, you gotta
join the Navy.
Yeah, you might
have to salute somebody
every once in a while,
but I-- it's better
than buying a rickety
old diesel boat
that sinks you to
the bottom of the ocean.
This is a reach,
even for us.
Okay.
"Luckenbach, Texas
(Back to the Basics of Love)"
playing
♪ The only two things in life
that make it worth living ♪
♪ Is guitars that tune good
and firm feelin' women ♪
♪ I don't need my name
in the marquee lights ♪
♪ I got my song
and I got you with me
tonight ♪
♪ Maybe it's time
we got back ♪
♪ To the basics of love ♪
♪ Let's go
to Luckenbach, Texas ♪
♪ With Waylon and Willie
and the boys ♪
♪ This successful life
we're livin' ♪
♪ Got us feuding like
the Hatfields and McCoys ♪
♪ Between Hank Williams'
pain songs ♪
♪ And Newbury's
train songs ♪
- ♪ And blue eyes cryin'
in the rain... ♪
- Hey.
I rang the doorbell,
but then I heard
the music, so...
I see you're busy.
I'll--
No, no,
I'm just trying out
a steam-powered CPU.
Look, I know
what this looks like--
like they parked
the loony bird out back
with his kiddy toys,
but I'll have you know
that these aren't just toys.
This is rail
transport modeling.
I got this back
when I was at Cardiff.
I just never
got around to it.
- ( music stops )
- What's going on?
I, uh-- I just came by
to give you something.
What is this, a PROM?
It's from the one
we reverse engineered.
You saved this.
I've always kept it
as kind of a private
touchstone.
Nice to have
when times are tough.
Sounds stupid, but...
it always kept me going.
Maybe you should
hold on to it.
Boy, it seems
like yesterday,
doesn't it?
Yeah, it seems
like forever ago.
Look, I heard about
what happened at Westgroup,
and if there's anything
I can do to help...
There may be a way
to repair the mainframe.
After I blew up Mutiny,
I tooled around
with the Sonaris code,
tried to see if there
was any way to reverse it.
You look good.
I'm glad.
W-what about
you and Sara?
Take care
of yourself, Gordon.
( music playing
in background )
There's a company off LBJ
that's letting go of their 3081.
That sounds promising.
- For a million bucks.
- ( coders laughing )
- I knew he was crazy!
- So, Rendon walks back up
to this girl and he goes,
"Look, you can unplug
the jukebox again
if you want to,
but I know
that deep down inside
you like Tom Petty,
because everyone
in this bar--
no, in America--
likes Tom Petty,
and it's only a matter of time
before you realize that."
( laughs )
Tom Rendon and
the Heartbreakers.
( all laugh )
You should
just call him.
Jesus.
The girls are down.
Oh, God, I am ready
for this day to be over.
You know, Telenet wants
to have a conference call
to discuss the rate hike.
It never ends.
Have you read this?
Upwards of six million
in damage
and they actually refer
to Sonaris by name.
Did you take
your medicine?
Yes, Nurse Ratched.
Westgroup's cover story
is that some network
assessment software
went awry.
I always hoped
one of my inventions
would go down in history.
I just never
knew it was gonna be
a goddamn computer virus.
Let's talk about
something else, huh?
( sighs )
Joe stopped by today.
I didn't mean Joe.
He looked like hell.
I don't think
he's doing well.
I'm sorry to hear that.
( slams drawer )
You know, he stopped by
to give me the PROM chip
from the IBM
we reverse engineered.
- He had saved it.
- Ha.
I've never
seen him like this.
I feel like
he could do something--
something desperate.
All because of what
Cameron did to him.
Doesn't that
disgust you?
I mean, even just
a little bit?
You know, I don't
think it's a good idea
for you to get
so worked up like this.
You know what
the doctor said.
She destroyed
his entire life,
and for what,
because he tried
to help her?
Well, it sounds like
you're just going with
Joe's version of events, then.
Because I think
he's telling the truth.
Do you remember what kind
of a partner he is?
When you were in business
with him last year,
all the things
that you accused him of?
- But this is different.
- Why?
Why is it
different now?
Now suddenly when
I experience the exact
same thing you do,
Joe is a nice guy?
Why is he the victim?
Joe might not be
the most trustworthy
person in the world,
but what Cameron did
to him is the most--
We did it.
Giving him the virus--
it was our idea,
Cameron's and mine.
You knew he was
leaving Westgroup.
- I told you that.
- Yeah.
Why would he have anything
to do with WestNet?
He already had
one foot in California.
The truth is,
it doesn't matter.
- What do you mean it--
- He's toxic.
You know that
as well as I do.
- What?
- Last month when
you were so worried
that someone
was stealing your idea,
well, that actually
happened to me.
- It wasn't just in my head.
- Who are you?
It's like I don't
even know you anymore.
- I mean, this entire year--
- Who am I?
You kept a serious illness
from me for nearly two months.
Frankly, I don't know
how honest you're being
with yourself about it
considering how
out of control
you've been.
- I am doing my best
to deal with this, okay?
- Oh, yeah.
I'm taking the pills,
I'm going to group.
- Which you think is a joke.
- I'm doing the--
- What?
- I saw you there
making fun of it.
You were not even trying.
So you're spying
on me in therapy?
Unbelievable, Donna.
Yeah, because you
keep things from me.
Well, it sounds like to me
we're keeping things
from each other.
Well, while we're
on the topic of secrets...
I would like to know
what happened in California.
Joanie told me
that you and Henry
got in a shouting match
that was apparently so bad
you had to take the girls
to a motel.
Why would you not
tell me that?
Because, Donna,
I had an affair!
( voice breaks )
What?
( whimpers )
It was one night.
It was meaningless.
It was absolutely stupid.
Do I regret it?
Yeah, every minute
of every day.
When I found out
I was sick,
I looked around
for my marriage
and it wasn't there.
You weren't there.
Maybe--
maybe this
has been broken
for a long time,
and we're the only ones
who don't know it.
Joanie.
Joanie, sweetheart.
( door slams )
( gurgling )
- Ow.
- ( sizzling )
- ( sputters )
- ( door opens, closes )
Hey.
You're here early.
I don't know
that Gordon and I love
each other anymore.
And I don't know--
I don't know
if we can fix it.
And I don't even know
if I wanna fix it.
I don't know
what it's like--
um, marriage.
Being married,
it's--
I don't know,
I won't pretend
to understand.
What you
and Gordon have,
or don't,
um, I mean,
that's something only
you two can figure out.
I do know that once
in a while, you know,
life can give us
a sign...
point us
to a different place,
make good things
come out of bad.
If it weren't
for Cardiff Electric,
there would've never
been a Mutiny, and...
you know,
if it weren't
for Gordon Clark,
I would've
never met you.
Listen, I don't want
to add to your misery here,
but the coffeemaker
is broken,
- so...
- ( laughs )
I think we should
move to California.
Here.
The diesel sub.
Look, if we can't
bring the mainframe
to Mutiny,
maybe we bring Mutiny
to the mainframe.
I think life
is giving us
a sign here.
Yes, we will have to beg,
borrow, and steal
the money for it,
but I--
it would be
a fresh start.
And I think that
that's something
that we could both use.
( birds chirping )
Hey.
What's up?
Can I come in?
I love what
you've done
to the place.
Listen, I was the one
who wrote the code
that took everything down.
Okay?
It was me--
You didn't do
anything wrong.
Yeah,
but neither did you.
I appreciate that,
but...
it doesn't really matter.
What about Sara?
Joe?
Damn it.
You're a good man.
You make it really difficult
for other people to see that,
but I see it,
and I suspect she
had something to do
with that.
That supposed
to make me feel better?
Look, I just came by
to give you this.
I went into the Sonaris code,
fixed the missing branch error.
Not only that,
this version targets
older copies.
It eradicates them.
I muscled it up
some, too,
so it'll inoculate machines
from future infection.
I mean,
it's-- it's one hell
of an antidote.
I mean, it won't undo
the damage done,
but maybe you can use it
to make things right.
Or a sign of good faith
to Jacob Wheeler.
I don't care
about Jacob Wheeler.
Then screw him.
Do it for Sara.
When we came to dinner
here that night,
you said to me,
"She makes all the suffering
of what we do worth it."
And I'm telling you,
that is not an easy thing
to come by.
And when you do,
it's--
it's even harder
to make it last,
and, I don't know.
Maybe it can't,
but...
I do know that you'll
hate yourself every day
if you don't at least try.
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
Hey, man,
come here.
( pats back )
( exhales )
Take care of yourself, Joe.
( door closes )
( chatter )
So I go in
and I tell him, I said,
"Now, it looks like
we're gonna finish the year
110% of quota."
My God, the accountant's
looking at the numbers.
He's going, "Well,
it says here 83%,
Mr. Bosworth.
Says here 83."
And I go, "Man, are you
including Bannister?
That's a $2 million
deal, man."
He goes, "Well-- well,
Bannister didn't close
in Q4."
And I said, "Sure, it did.
I closed that son of a bitch
on the 35th of December myself."
( all laughing )
I tell ya,
he's full of these.
Get him going,
he won't stop.
Well, James,
you were right
about your daddy.
A month in, he's already
whipping this place
into shape.
I had no doubt.
Well, it's a damn fine
place to work, I gotta say.
And thank you
for inviting me to this
big muckety-muck lunch here.
Ah, I know you're
only manager level now
and we're not
fast-tracking
anything here,
but, well, we thought
it'd be good for you to hear
how things are operating
at the upper levels,
have your voice
in the room.
And, Mr. Stern,
it goes without saying
that I sincerely
appreciate the invite
to sit down with
the senior team today.
A junior boy like me
is a guppy at this table.
Well, without you,
we wouldn't have John.
Well...
You know, I-- I must've told
this one about a million times,
but I remember
when I was a kid,
a manager comes in and...
( laughs )
...he says, "Now, Joe,
you're under quota.
We need to be
in the black."
So I look at him,
I toss my coffee cup
up on the forecast,
and I say, "Now how's that
for bein' in the black?"
( muffled laughter )
- ( conversation
continues indistinctly )
- ( ringing )
( birds chirping )
( music playing
in background )
Donna?
Whoa, Gordon,
what do you want?
- Hey, where's Donna?
- Okay, Gordon,
I think you need to
back off for a little bit.
Damn it, this has
nothing to do with you.
Gordon, I want you
out of my house.
- Hey.
- Is she here?
- What the heck is going on?
Who?
Oh, Christ,
I thought she was
with you.
Gordon, what are you
talking about?
I can't find Joanie.
She's not at the house.
She's not
at your parents' house.
- Haley said she ran away.
- Okay-- ( sighs )
You haven't
seen her at all?
Sometimes she rides bikes
with Heather after school.
( car door closes )
Okay, well,
just let me know.
Thanks.
- Did you--
- I didn't see her
on Marion
and I went all the way
to Belt Line.
- Oh, what about the, um--
- She's not in the cul-de-sac
and she's not
down by the creek either.
Okay, so, uh,
her backpack is gone,
her lunch box is gone,
her sleeping bag--
Donna, I need you
to know that I didn't--
look, this wasn't me.
I didn't--
God damn it,
I didn't lose her.
Haley said
that she ran away, okay?
Donna, I need you to know
that this wasn't me.
Mommy, Daddy, look.
- What is that?
- It's our camping lantern.
I had to leave.
I told a secret.
And it made you
not in love anymore.
Hey, hey, listen.
Your mom and I may
get into an argument
sometimes, okay?
But it's never
because of you, okay?
Are you gonna
get divorced?
Mommy and Daddy love
each other very much.
But there are some things
that we need to talk about.
So why don't you
go up to the house,
give your sister
a big old hug,
and you two can pick out
what kind of pizza to get
for dinner, okay?
Good girl.
Come here.
( sighs )
( door opens, closes )
I don't want
to be the woman
that leaves her husband
when he's sick,
but that doesn't
mean I won't.
I thought a lot
about what you said
and I think you're right.
This marriage
isn't working,
so we need to do
what's best for the kids
and what's best for us.
So here are my terms.
You're gonna
write a check.
It's gonna be for almost
as much money as we have,
and we're gonna use it
to buy a 3033 mainframe.
Not only that, you are
gonna help me fix it up
and get it running again.
The mainframe
is in Daly City,
so, yes, you are going
to move to California.
We all are.
That is what it costs
to fix our marriage.
So what is this,
extortion?
No, it's an investment.
Not just in a mainframe,
but in something that
you believe in
or something I thought
you believed in
before you did
what you did.
Look, I know it was wrong
and I'm sorry.
I told you
it was a mistake.
No, I can't-- I don't
want to talk about that.
( exhales )
Cameron is going
to offer you a job
at Mutiny
and you are
gonna take it.
You want me
to work at Mutiny?
No, I want you
to work with me.
And this taking turns,
this one person holding
the kite strings
while the other person
is off chasing something,
that isn't working.
You really think
that moving to California
is gonna fix everything?
I don't know.
But it's the best thing
I could come up with.
And I do know
that if we stay here,
we are not gonna make it.
Sir, it's already
been three hours.
I suggest you make
an appointment,
come back at a more
reasonable time.
Hey.
I was wondering
how long you'd wait.
( chuckles )
I'm surprised, Joe.
You are persistent.
I'll give you that much.
- I, uh--
- Ooh.
I wanted to show
you something.
( computer screeches, beeps )
See, after my time
at Cardiff, I went away.
I decided I should
do things differently,
operate from a place
of total authenticity.
Be open, be human,
do the right thing.
But the truth is,
no one else
made that pact
with themselves.
So why should I?
What is this?
Damn it.
Your computer's now
infected with a virus,
the same one
that took down Westgroup.
It's a malignant
fetch program,
and it will spread
from this box
to every other
networked computer
in your organization.
Oh, my God.
I'm calling security.
Security?
You want security?
Why, 'cause you
don't trust me?
You don't know
what I'll do.
Who knows
what I'll do?
When there's no trust,
you're vulnerable.
Just because you play
by the rules doesn't mean
anyone else will.
- So what should you do?
- ( hangs up phone )
You should
protect yourself,
build a wall.
Not like that,
like this.
- ( computer beeps )
- ( keyboard clacking )
Do you know
what a vaccine is?
It's not medicine;
it's a little bit
of the virus.
You take a little bit
of something bad
so you can never be
hurt like that again.
- ( keyboard clacks )
- ( computer beeps )
Check it out.
Ahem.
- ( keyboard clacks )
- ( computer beeps )
It's--
how'd you do that?
With an antidote
to the poison.
Sure, this program
only protects your machine
from this specific virus,
but the real product here
is security,
a shield against those
who would hurt you,
perhaps because of
their own carelessness
or simply because
they want to destroy you.
And after the national exposure
of what happened at Westgroup,
entire organizations
are going to be ravenous
for this.
The real security
is trusting no one.
And you came up with this
all on your own?
- Pizza's here!
- Yay!
All right, guys,
be careful.
Don't burn yourselves,
okay?
( phone ringing )
- Hello?
- Joe: Gordon, it's me.
Hey.
"Create the sickness,
sell the cure."
- What?
- "Create the sickness,
sell the cure."
You remember when you
came over to my place?
- I can't talk right now, Joe.
- No, no, no, I took
your advice, Gordon,
and I turned this
into something good,
really good.
That's great.
I'm glad, but,
look, I gotta go.
No, no, you gotta
hear me out.
You'll be glad you did.
We should celebrate, Gordon.
We've got
an incredible opportunity.
What are you
talking about?
I'm talking about
you and me together,
partnering again.
What-- what are you
doing right now?
We gotta talk this through.
I'll come over.
Look, I can't
do this anymore.
Donna and I are
moving to California.
Great, we can
do this in California.
In fact, we should.
I'm going to work
for Mutiny.
I need to focus
on my family right now.
You're going
to work for Mutiny?
Listen, Joe,
I-- I didn't--
( birds chirping )
Whoa.
Good morning.
So, here's my offer.
While Mutiny is no longer
a games company,
we are relocating
to California
and could use
a talented hand
like yours
as we attempt to take
our service national.
I don't need
an answer right away.
I just--
you can decide
if you want
to be on the 8:45
out of DFW tonight.
And even if you
don't want the job,
just come anyways.
It's a free plane ticket.
That's not a lot
of time to decide.
Or maybe it's
just enough time
not to overthink it.
"Heaven" playing
( coders chatting )
Look, if she's
in love with a guy
named Marty in 1955,
then she has a kid,
she names him Marty
and that kid grows up
to look exactly like
the Marty that
she fell in love with,
they're either
gonna bone
or she's gonna have
a nervous breakdown
or both.
Or I don't care.
Just shut up and stop
talking about it.
Hey, Lev.
♪ The name of the bar ♪
♪ The bar
is called Heaven... ♪
You know, I was
worried about them,
pulling them
out of school
and away from
their friends
and my folks,
but they are
the happiest people
on this plane.
( girls chatting )
♪ They play it once again ♪
You know...
we could
be happy again.
I really believe that.
And who knows?
Maybe when we get
to California...
I don't know,
maybe we'll
have another.
♪ Heaven ♪
♪ Heaven is a place... ♪
( chuckles )
I'm gonna go
use the bathroom
before we take off.
♪ Nothing ever happens ♪
♪ There is a party ♪
♪ Everyone is there ♪
♪ Everyone will leave ♪
♪ At exactly
the same time... ♪
( crying )
♪ It's hard to imagine ♪
♪ That nothing at all... ♪
Flight attendant over intercom:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome aboard
United Flight 242
to San Francisco.
If everyone could please
take your seats,
we will be pushing back
momentarily.
♪ Exactly the same time ♪
♪ It's hard to imagine ♪
♪ That nothing at all ♪
♪ Could be so exciting ♪
- ♪ Could be
this much fun... ♪
- ( coders cheering )
( cheering continues )
Bosworth:
All right, ladies.
You know,
I never thought
I'd say this,
but I guess
it's time to move out
to the Left Coast.
( cheering, laughing )
- ( chuckles )
- Coder: That's awesome.
Are you ready for this?
- Okay.
- ♪ Heaven is a place... ♪
( lock clanks )
♪ A place where nothing ♪
♪ Nothing ever happens. ♪
Gordon:
Son of a...
( plane engine whines )
You'll have
the entire floor.
Enough space
for 100-plus desks.
But because of the prime
Bay Area location,
I'll just let you know
I have several other
interested parties.
I'll take it.
We'll need
to discuss price?
Then I'll go get
the paperwork.
( music playing )