"They All Laughed"
playing
♪ They all laughed
at Christopher Columbus ♪
♪ When he said the world
was round, aha ♪
♪ They all laughed
when Edison recorded sound... ♪
Ahem. Ooh.
♪ They all laughed
at Wilbur and his brother ♪
♪ When they said
that man could fly ♪
♪ They told Marconi
wireless was a phony... ♪
Is he doing
Frank Sinatra?
He can do Frank Zappa
for all I care.
As long as it
holds him off.
All right,
let's cycle her
through again.
- Donna: Her?
- Yeah, her.
Temperamental,
high-maintenance,
only responds
to the right touch.
Yeah, well, I've been
touching this thing
for six months
and he still
hasn't turned on.
♪ They all laughed
at Rockefeller Center ♪
♪ Now they're
fightin' to get in ♪
♪ They all laughed at Mutiny
and our cotton gin... ♪
( cheering )
♪ They all said
we never would be happy ♪
♪ They laughed at us,
and how ♪
♪ But, oh, ho-ho ♪
♪ Who's got
the last laugh now? ♪
Hey, could you make them
hurry up downstairs?
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- We're gonna lose this dude.
Hey, it's nice to see
some ladies here for once.
( chuckles )
Probably should've waited
to schedule the celebration
of a working mainframe
until the mainframe was
actually, you know, working.
Hey, Bos says hurry up.
That reporter's gonna leave.
Donna:
Yeah.
All right, try that.
( sighs )
Still not booting up.
( inhales )
You okay?
Yeah.
Scale of one to 10?
I'm fine.
Do you want to lie down?
Yeah, of course
I want to lie down.
I've been awake
for 20 hours.
I just...
Scale of one to 10?
Two.
Three, max.
Mm, let me check
the power unit again.
And now, please,
without further ado,
let's welcome
our founder,
Cameron Howe.
- Come on.
- ( crowd cheering )
Come on.
Hey.
( cheering continues )
♪ They laughed at me
wanting you ♪
♪ Said it would be... ♪
- Hi.
- Man: Hey.
- Cameron Howe.
- Ross Weaver, "InfoWorld."
- Mm.
- Quite a party, but, um,
maybe a little premature.
( chuckles )
Seriously,
how much longer?
Um...
Oh, God, somebody
put a cigarette out
on this wire wrap.
You know, once we're
our own network,
Cameron and I can get back
to what really matters.
I'm sure she's eager
to get you back.
( sighs )
Booting up?
- ( loud pop )
- ( mainframes whirring )
It's on!
( cheering )
( muffled cheering )
Oh!
( cheering continues )
The Death Star is online
and operational.
( gasps )
Alderaan will never
know what hit it.
Hey, Donna.
Cam wants you upstairs
like right now.
Yes.
Let's go celebrate.
♪ Because, ho-ho-ho,
who's got the last laugh? ♪
♪ Hee-hee-hee,
let's make the past laugh ♪
All:
♪ Har-har-har, who's got
the last laugh now? ♪
All right!
Suck it, Telenet,
you faxed us
your last invoice!
Bosworth:
Whoa, ho!
Whoa, whoa, hey, hey!
- ( popping )
- ( crowd gasping )
That is way more fireworks
than we talked about.
( cheering )
( chanting )
Speech! Speech!
Bosworth:
Hey, come on.
( chanting continues )
- ( cheering )
- Donna: Okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, first of all,
I would like to welcome
our guest, Ross Weaver,
from "InfoWorld."
I hope you've all had
a chance to talk to him.
He'll be covering
our relaunch.
- Hide the drugs.
- ( laughing )
As you know,
we hit 100,000 users
last week.
Yeah!
But,
more importantly,
it's a banner day,
you guys.
Our Independence Day!
( cheering )
Cameron:
Oh, oh, one more thing.
This is very important.
John Bosworth
is officially
a grandfather.
( crowd cheering )
Look, I know it feels
like we got to California
two minutes ago,
but we can't slow down now.
We are continuing
to expand user experience
on the network...
Avatar modification,
building out neighborhoods.
We have a ton
of really important
deadlines coming up
and we are counting
on you guys.
We know how hard it was
to leave all our friends
and family in Texas,
but we are so impressed
with your commitment
- and we just want--
- Speaking of commitment,
there is one person
I would especially
like to thank--
my husband Gordon Clark.
- ( applause )
- Donna: Come on up.
Crowd:
Gordo!
I just want to say
thank you so much
for believing
in this crazy idea
and slaving away
in the basement with me,
because we couldn't have
done it without you.
I couldn't have.
Crowd:
Whoo!
Cameron:
All right, come on,
let's get back to the party.
"Shut Us Down" playing
( crowd applauding )
- ( sighs )
- ♪ I got a 'lectric guitar ♪
♪ And half a bottle
of warm beer ♪
♪ I got some funny ideas
about what sounds good... ♪
( imitating Donna )
I couldn't have done it
without you, Gordon.
Yeah, couldn't have done it
without your money.
( chuckles )
♪ Better shut us down ♪
♪ Better shut us down. ♪
( theme music playing )
Unbelievable.
This is
a complete hatchet job.
Gordon:
I know it hurts,
but, trust me,
there's no such thing
as bad press.
And the Pro got creamed
in the trades
and it still
outsold the Giant
by a factor of five.
No, this is different.
This is bad.
What, let me guess.
You're gonna kill him?
No, it's his facts
that are killing us.
We're a quarter
of the size of CompuServe,
we have less infrastructure
than The Source,
nowhere near the investment
visibility of Q-Link.
I hate it,
but he's right.
- What's up, squirt?
- "Family Circus" still sucks.
- That's true.
- Hey, language.
Language.
- Where is Joanie?
- Getting dressed.
He calls you upstarts,
says you're a welcome addition
of heart and vitality
to the Valley landscape.
The guy's--
that's great.
Yeah, he's also got us
going under by '88.
Well, if you're that
worried about it,
issue a press release
full of stats and revenue
and, you know, tell your
version of the story.
What? No one reads
press releases.
They read magazines,
like this one.
Well, then,
we might as well
write an obituary.
- Oh, shit.
- Haley and Gordon: Language.
Sorry, honey.
I've got to meet
with Joanie's principal
today at 4:00.
Why?
She got in a fight
on Monday.
Okay, when were you
gonna tell me about that?
I'm sorry.
Completely forgot.
She win, at least?
The school wants
a parent meeting.
Uh, we have a development
meeting at 4:00.
- I know.
- So, can't he do it?
Okay, I'll give
you guys a minute.
( keyboard clacking )
Roar!
Got you.
You totally didn't know
I was in there.
Yeah, well,
you're totally busted
for the fight
you got into at school.
Whatever.
I kicked her ass.
- Really?
- Go ahead.
You know you want to.
What?
( imitates modem
screeching )
You're such
a little brat.
- And I--
- ( modem screeching )
I know you're frustrated.
I'm frustrated, too.
We're five people living
on top of each other,
and that's--
Donna, I'm frustrated
because this was supposed
to be temporary.
- It is temporary.
- No, it's been six mo--
- ( rumbling )
- Oh, shit.
Haley, sweetheart,
get under the table.
- ( screams )
- Joanie!
- Mom!
- It's okay, it's okay.
- ( rattling )
- It's all right.
You okay?
- Was that...?
- Yes, it was. Hang on,
there's broken glass here.
What should we do?
Should we stay in the doorway
or go outside?
You're fine.
You're fine right
where you are.
Joanie, baby,
are you okay?
I'm fine, just don't
freak out on me.
Sorry, do you think
that was just a preview?
- Like a bigger one's coming?
- ( whimpers )
- Or is that
the final thing?
- Hey, listen.
- You're not helping.
- Don't be such a wimp, Haley.
- Hey, Joanie.
- Your sister's scared.
Be nice.
- You always
take her side.
- Joanie.
Hey, listen, guys.
( all gasp )
Jesus, people,
it's toast.
Donna:
My, don't you look
out of this world.
Cameron:
Pretty rad, right?
The antennae just
rolled out this week,
along with sunglasses,
regular glasses,
and a mohawk
customization.
You should totally
get the mohawk.
Oh, we should
totally get going.
Let's start with Main Street
and then the smaller places.
( gasps )
Oh, there's Sledgehammer.
Did you hear CompuServe's
expanding to Japan?
And GEnie added
10,000 users last quarter.
At least CBS might
back out of Trintex.
Great, then it's just
IBM and Sears.
Seams kind of dead
on here, doesn't it?
Well, yeah,
at 9:00 a.m. on a Tuesday
and the system's
like a casino floor
in the morning.
It's only the hardcores.
But, hey, look
at Comic Book Corner.
Donna:
Oh, the niche room
metrics
are off the charts
'round the clock.
That place is rowdy, man.
There's more fights
than a Hells Angels bar.
Well, I guess it's good
that these guys' glasses
are digital, then.
Nice.
Oh, hold on a sec.
Guy's got
a 1311 with a modded
thumbfire button.
Jeez, do you know
everybody on here?
( computer beeping )
( keyboard clacks )
( groans )
And then here we are.
64,000 pixels
of prime, undeveloped
real estate.
It can be whatever
we want it to be.
It's got to be--
it's gotta be
something great.
( knocks )
Ryan.
What's up?
Sorry, I didn't mean
to interrupt.
Are we still on?
I know we said 9:00.
- Maybe it was 9:15.
- No, it was 9:00.
Yeah, no, 9:00.
Come on in.
( mouths )
I don't know.
( computers whirring )
( muffled footsteps
thudding )
( thudding continues )
( muffled laughing,
chattering )
( muffled music playing )
( footsteps continue
thudding )
Okay, here's another way
to look at it.
Community looks like this.
No, uh, it looks like this.
Well, no, like this.
Just-- okay, blah, blah,
chatting, chatting, chatting.
We dress it up with
a sprite-scaling interface,
but underneath
it's just paint-by-numbers.
You know, here's a room,
chat in it.
I think it's a little more
than paint-by-numbers.
To discount the meaningful
human interaction.
No, no, no, it works,
it's fine.
It's like vanilla ice cream,
but it's...
So, here are the users
and here's private chat.
And the users,
they're talking, talking.
"Hey, what's going on?
Let's get to know
each other more."
So they go to private chat.
And then private chat
is just PETSCII because--
1977.
You know how your mom
always says to close
the door behind you?
These two users,
they-- they leave,
and they
don't close the...
Okay, so,
all these other people
here are saying,
"Hey, what
are you guys doing?
Where are they going?
I want to check that out."
And so they--
they go, like that.
And so...
that's your problem.
Have you guys ever seen
"The Conversation"?
Which conversation?
Wait, the--
the Gene Hackman movie?
Exactly.
Uh...
People think
private chat is private.
But because of the way
somebody wrote it--
- The way I wrote it.
- Donna: Wait, wait.
You're telling me
that people are hacking
private chats?
Sure, um, big-time.
Look.
So, see this
little guy here?
That's the hacker.
Totally masked.
The asterisk
is a prompt for data.
You can't mask that.
Hold on.
How did you get this?
These are private
chat transcripts.
Easy, I just walked
through the gaping holes
that the hackers did.
- Ryan.
- No, you cannot do that.
Sure, I can.
I just--
Don't do it again.
I mean it.
That's a direct violation
of our user agreement.
Yeah, okay.
Um, totally right.
Uh, but here's my idea.
So, you connect users
outside public room,
but to different
encryption points first,
then to each other.
You cover tracks,
you rebuild private chat
separate from Mutiny,
but also still
talking to Mutiny
outside Mutiny.
Second
but separate Mutiny.
Users here,
here, and here
network, remote,
program, hub,
RSA filters
one, two, three.
No cache.
Voila.
Ryan, that's
an entirely new
and very expensive
something
using techniques
that our coders
don't even know, so--
I can do it.
You still have a ton
of sprite rendering for me.
Then put one of the guys
who can't do this on it.
Ryan, we're not doing it.
Okay.
- But here's another idea.
- ( groans )
Okay, you know what?
Ryan, why don't you
just send it to us
electronically?
Okay.
Cool.
No problem.
Great, really looking
forward to checking it out.
Oh, and just to say it
one more time,
something like this
is way better for Mutiny
than putting a bow tie
on an avatar.
Got it.
Yeah, thanks.
( door opens )
"One Way Ticket" playing
♪ Give me a one-way ticket ♪
♪ Give me a one-way fare ♪
♪ Give me
a one-way ticket... ♪
- It's happening again!
- ( rumbling )
( laughing )
It was funny
the first six times.
Next person that does it
is gonna wear their
underwear as a hat.
( bangs )
Cut it out,
you cretins.
Every time you screw around,
it rains down debris
on the mainframe.
Look.
There's a date now.
Dude, that's today.
If you ask me, it's got
Reagan's fingerprints
all over it.
- Jesus.
- Hello, remember
lasers in space?
Okay, it starts with fear
because nobody wants to die
in a nuclear blast.
And then, one by one,
they take away your rights
until you're
Sieg Heilin' Ronnie
and bowing down
before Ed Meese.
Bodie:
It's gotta be
some gay thing.
You know, like AIDS.
Real sensitive, dude.
Wonderboy:
Maybe it's
a religious thing,
like Pat Robertson
saying the world's
gonna end again.
Gordon:
You idiots.
- It's Joe MacMillan.
- Wait, what?
- No way!
- Nyet.
- Oh, that's better than Reagan.
- The antivirus guy?
- How are you so sure?
- They were partners.
Dave:
Is it true
he knows Madonna?
Like, really knows her?
I heard his first client
was the CIA.
Yeah, no,
that was Oracle.
Didn't MacMillan, like,
steal your idea
and make
a gazillion dollars?
Yeah.
But I'm suing the son
of a bitch, aren't I?
♪ Give me a one-way ticket,
oh, yeah ♪
♪ Get me out of here. ♪
No, I slept
right through it.
( chuckled )
I woke up and some water
had sloshed out the toilet bowl,
but that was about it.
- But, look, Terry,
before the big one hits...
- ( knock on door )
I want to get
this modem order
sorted out.
You're damn right, v.22.
Hey, and I want
the wholesale number
for that.
Ter-- oh, come on, man.
I can walk right across
the street to USR
and get high-speed
transfer for that.
Just--
all right, well,
call me back when
you want to talk,
when you've come
to your senses,
all right?
Thanks.
( sniffles )
Look, you need to--
you need to invest
in some improvements
in the mainframe room.
It's a disaster
waiting to happen.
All right,
whatever you need.
No problem.
( sighs )
There something else,
Gordon?
( Arki speaking Russian )
How do you do it?
How do you deal
with all this nonsense?
Oh, well...
You know, it's like
feeding animals
at the zoo.
Dangle a couple kippers out
for them and they dance
and keep them
locked up in their cages
the rest of the day.
( no audible dialogue )
You talking about
the queens of the jungle,
that's a different story.
Advice?
( phone ringing )
I find it wise
not to interfere
with the brain trust.
( ringing continues )
They run the place.
I just work here.
Bosworth.
Joe:
Boy or girl?
- Excuse me?
- Boy or girl?
Your grandchild.
Oh, it's, uh--
he's a boy.
Who is this?
Joe:
Come on, did you really
forget about me?
- Joe?
- I just wanted to call
and say I'm happy for you.
Hey, how did you
even get the--
Be well, John.
( clicks, dial tone )
Yeah, 100,000 users
sounds good,
but what really matters
is how long they stay on.
And moving that number
is proving
a lot more difficult
than it looks.
Hey, listen.
Once I get
the mainframe solid,
I was thinking...
I don't know,
I was thinking about maybe
pursuing other opportunities.
Wh--
We did what we set out
to do with the 3033
and, come on,
there's not really
much more for me to do.
Well...
I want you
to be happy.
Hi.
I'm guessing you two
are Joanie's mom and dad.
Oh, are you
Jennifer's mom?
Most of the time.
People also call me Diane.
Of course.
I'm Donna.
Oh, Gordon, sorry.
Look, as far as Joanie goes,
I know how hard it is
to be the new kid in school.
She has my sympathy.
But I think
what this boils down to
is Jennifer is
just pretty pissed
at her father and me.
We're going
through proceedings.
It's been a bit rocky.
Pr-- proceedings?
Divorce.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, I'm not.
Believe me, it's better
for everyone.
Except Jennifer,
who's lashing out.
Anyway, so, I apologize
and I hope it hasn't
caused you too much grief.
( soft laugh )
Uh, Mr. and Mrs. Clark.
Oh, Mrs. Gould.
Principal Wilcox
will see you now.
Great.
( keyboard clacking )
- Hey, Cam.
- Hi.
Hey, did you tell
anyone else about
my grandson?
No.
Should I not
have announced it?
Nah, nah.
I'm just wondering.
Hey, Bos.
Come here.
What?
Uh, I need you
to give Ryan a raise.
Just bump him up 15%.
All right,
that's a good call.
The kid's been doing
a bang-up job.
- Yeah.
- All right.
( chatter )
( coders chattering )
Hey, I'm working here.
Dude, we're all going
to Burger King.
Come to lunch with us.
I brought today.
I'm good.
Come on,
this Boo Radley-in-
the-basement thing
is getting
kind of creepy.
We're offering you
a flame-broiled way
out of here.
Look, I don't have time.
This is important, okay?
Seriously?
( scoffs )
Whatever.
What a slave.
What, does he sleep late?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Why?
I'm the one changing
in the middle
of a little girls' room.
Thank you again for being
so understanding.
Kids'll be kids.
Maybe Jennifer can come
play with Joanie sometime.
Well, that would be odd
considering they don't
like each other.
Oh, um, I'm sorry.
I'll talk to Joanie.
I like it that we're
both raising girls
who are fighters.
Don't you?
What?
I'm just glad
you didn't get suspended.
( sighs )
I know you think
you hate California.
I know it's--
it's hard here.
But...
we have to commit.
Otherwise, it's never
gonna feel like home.
( crying )
The whole house
was shaking.
Sweetie, you okay?
I'm fine.
- You sure?
- Fine.
( sniffles )
We are gonna be okay.
I promise.
It's a raise, son.
You won today.
Did Cameron or Donna
mention anything else?
Is it less
than you asked for?
I didn't ask
for anything.
I just pitched them
some ideas.
I'm sure they'll reach out
when and if the time is right.
Hmm?
I'm sure
they'll let you know.
( door opens )
( TV announcer
speaking Spanish )
Blue Moon Detective?
- Oh, hey, CamHowe.
- Hey.
Nice to meet you...
in person.
It's weird meeting people
this way, isn't it?
It's like you jumped
out of my computer screen
or something,
like you're not real.
Yeah, yeah,
Mutiny's pretty cool
in that...
I haven't been on long.
I only just discovered it.
How about you?
Uh, I work there,
actually.
Oh, wow.
That's gotta be fun.
Yeah, you know,
it's harder than it looks.
Is this the gear?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Please go ahead.
Um, I think
it's in there somewhere.
Oh, yeah.
Hope the paint's okay.
Yeah, no, he was
a big Niners fan, right?
Yeah, he was.
Uh, how do you know
about that?
What?
That he was a--
wait, did we talk
about him?
- Yeah.
- My son.
Yeah, yeah.
You posted in the grief
and support room.
And I'm so sorry
for your loss,
but the, um, joystick
looks great, so--
We didn't meet
on the grief board.
We met in the tech room.
Right.
That's where we met,
but I saw that you posted
in the grief
and support room
and then--
All I posted was--
I mean, I just posted
that I had lost someone.
I never said
anything about...
I just had private chats
about him with other people.
- Not anything--
- No.
We never talked
about him, never.
How-- how the hell
do you know about that?
How do you know
about him at all?
I...
I think I should go.
How do you know
about my son?
Those conversations
were supposed to be private.
( whirring )
( distant music, chatter )
( clicking )
( coders laughing )
- ( popping )
- ( laughing )
What, can you blame me?
All this to add
graphics capability
to chat.
Whatever keeps
the users on longer.
Seriously doubt
it'll work long.
Yeah, but this
LZW compression
is pretty cool.
Lev: You really think
people are gonna stick
around because of GIFs?
- It's pronounced "jif."
- No way. Hard G, "gif."
I heard "jif,"
but it's cool if you
want to be wrong.
Hey, look, everyone,
it's "Jordon."
Hey, you guys know I can
hear everything you say
down in the mainframe room?
Yeah,
can you hear this?
( farts )
( coders laugh )
Marty, I worry
about you.
What I couldn't help
but overhear
is you guys whining
about having a long night.
Back in the Cardiff
kill room,
we developed
a little technique
for pushing through
nights like this.
Called it
the "Tandy-Shandy."
One keeps you sharp,
and the other's--
the other's a beer.
( laughs )
Well, we've got
our own technique,
if you're interested.
Ooh.
( pops tab )
( laughing )
And that, gentlemen,
is how you jerk off
a dinosaur.
( laughing )
( pounds table )
All right, now, look,
I'm gonna make a phone call.
When I come back,
I wanna hear about that Amiga.
All right?
( dial tone )
( touch-tones beeping )
( line ringing )
James:
Bosworths, leave a message.
- ( beeps )
- Hey there, son.
It's Dad.
I suppose you're getting used
to calling yourself that
right about now, huh?
( chuckles )
Oh, hell, I bet
it's getting late
in Rockwall.
Dang it.
I hope I didn't wake
my little sweet pea up there.
I'm sorry
I keep missing you.
I just want to hear
every little detail
about that kid.
It would occur to me
I don't even know
the little fella's name.
Did you guys decide
on one or--
( beeps )
So...
( coughs )
So I go over
to Joe's house,
you know, I'm expecting
to see this guy swinging
from the rafters.
Holy shit.
But, surprise,
he's alive.
He opens the door.
I mean, he looks like hell,
but he's alive.
So, I go in.
You know, the whole place
is cleaned out.
And I can see it,
his whole life gone,
destroyed.
It's exactly
what I had thought,
which is exactly
why I stayed up all night
reversing
the Sonaris code.
You know, honestly,
I really wanted to help him.
So I gave him the disk
out of the goodness
of my heart.
We hugged.
Joe MacMillan
knows how to hug?
Next thing you know,
I wake up,
I'm reading
about $10 million
in financing,
all based
on my software.
That's insane.
Yeah.
Of course a guy like that
would steal your idea.
I mean, he's too stupid
to come up with one of his own.
No, no, no, no, no.
Don't you do that.
Don't you
underestimate him.
That's when
he's most dangerous.
No, Joe's...
Joe's brilliant.
And when you're
in that guy's thrall,
you know,
it feels like a drug.
You know, you--
you feel...
like the most important
person in the world.
And that's when you wake up
with your neck slit,
bleeding all over
the floor.
( door opens )
What is that?
They're Ryan's
private chat transcripts.
He'd already
printed them off
and I figured
maybe there'd be
some answers in here,
but what if we do
go under by '88?
I mean, everything
we went through last year,
all the battles we fought,
moving everything out here,
everyone, our--
leaving our families
and our friends.
What if we did all that
just to, what,
putter around out here
for a couple of years
and then disappear like
we were never even here
in the first place?
No, moving here
wasn't a mistake.
Here.
There's gotta be
something in here.
Well, there's all kinds
of reasons that people
are signing off.
They're getting
along so well,
they want to talk
on the phone.
Maybe that's obvious.
Sometimes they even
want to meet up in person.
Or they want
to make a trade.
I met up with
the joystick guy earlier.
Then why did you
go to Fry's?
Because when I met up
with him in person,
he turned out to be
a total creep.
( bottle cap clatters )
Transactional interactions?
Like, what if you didn't
have to sign off
when you wanted
to make a trade?
- You could just...
- Do it online.
Okay, sure.
That's just what you did,
but that's only one reason--
Okay, look.
We're never gonna
stop people
from talking
on the phone, right?
And we don't want to
because that's...
a genuine connection.
But with
transactions...
Here, look!
This is about bootlegs.
"I've got the Venice show
from last fall."
"I've got the whole
summer up north."
Here's another one!
Here. How about
my "WrestleMania '85"
for your Hagler/Hearns
"War" VHS?
It's not gonna be
every time,
but there could be
enough of these
that it warrants
building something
so that people are doing
this interaction on Mutiny.
Even if people
aren't already trading,
it's a brand-new type
of interaction
that could draw in
more and more users.
Yeah, yeah.
If it's good enough.
It just has to be
good enough.
Okay, that's...
( sighs )
That's interesting.
I've never seen that before.
But is this it?
( sighs )
I-I don't know.
I've never
seen it before, either,
and I feel like
we've seen a lot.
This could be
the sort of thing
that would make people
really sit up
and pay attention.
- But is it it?
- Right?
'Cause it needs
to be it,
'cause we're only
gonna get one shot
at this out here.
- ( door opens )
- Well...
( door closes )
Yo.
Everything okay
with the mainframe?
Yep.
Took care of it.
Anyways, it gave me an excuse
to hang out with the coders.
- You know.
- Tandy-Shandy?
Gordon:
And then some.
Oof.
You guys working
on something?
Mm.
Oh, yeah,
we were just coming up
with some ideas--
Ah, I'll leave it
to the brain trust.
( growls )
Okay,
that was so weird.
So, what do you think?
I think let's do it.
Yeah, I think so, too.
But if this is gonna work,
we're gonna have
to trust each other.
Reading private chats
is a violation of our
user agreement.
Can we close the back door
of that code?
Yeah, sure.
No problem.
You're high.
Yeah, so are you.
Oh, hey, hey.
Hey.
You smell like
Berkeley, Gordon.
- I could take a shower.
- No.
When's the last time
our bedroom smelled like weed?
That's the great thing
about California.
Our bedroom
can smell like weed
whenever we want.
( laughs )
( modem screeching )
( electricity crackling )
( chattering )
- ( chatter quiets )
- Man: Shh, shh, shh.
( shutter clicks )
Fear--
it's a natural reaction
to moving closer to the truth.
You know, ever since
I started MacMillan Utility,
I've been accused
of selling fear.
But let me ask you...
is it fear?
Or is it truth?
( shutter clicks )
How sure is our footing?
Yesterday morning,
many of us were reminded
of that question
when we literally felt
the ground move beneath us.
We live in a world
that is constantly shifting,
sometimes
bringing us together
and sometimes
pulling us apart.
James:
Hey, Pop, don't worry
about calling late.
We already gave up on sleep.
( chuckles )
Anyway, uh, I thought
you'd like to know
we are going with
Samuel John.
( keyboard clacking )
Joe:
Who are our friends?
Who are our enemies?
What's gonna happen to us?
Are we safe?
What I created has grown.
Now, some of you...
( chuckles )
...even call MacMillan Utility
the gold standard
in corporate
antivirus protection.
But in the meantime,
I've been asking myself,
"What should the price
of security really be?
How much should we pay
to feel safe?"
Wait, here's another one
from that same
ancient tradition.
The whole secret of existence
is to have no fear at all.
Never fear
what will become of you.
Depend on no one.
Only in the moment
that you reject all help
are you really free.
- ( crowd murmuring )
- Only by moving past fear
can we ever arrive
at the truth.
And the truth is
freedom from fear
is a right,
not a commodity.
I know what
you're thinking.
I charge
my corporate clients
millions.
Well, they can afford it.
But tomorrow
I'm releasing
our user version,
Citadel,
the version I created
for all of you.
Mainframe-quality security
for your personal computer.
( applause )
Wait, wait.
And I'm charging you...
nothing.
( applause, cheering )
For you...
it will be
absolutely free.
( cheering )
Mr. MacMillan,
I've got a question
from "InfoWorld."
( music playing )