- ( music playing )
- ( seagull screeching )
Donna:
On our network, users can
already have a conversation,
send mail,
share information,
connect.
But this promises
to be far more.
This is the world's first
virtual handshake deal.
- A trade.
- A trade made
on your computer
that swaps tangible items
between users.
You get everything
you want without ever
leaving your home.
You do everything
from your keyboard.
The only person
you'll ever see
is the mailman.
We're looking
for the right partner.
We've currently got
100,000 dedicated users
and we're growing,
so expansion like this
requires another level
of funding.
We need to add
more bodies to
the coding team,
- enhance our interface,
and purchase--
- How much?
In the back of our
prospectus you'll find
a detailed breakdown of--
I saw the number.
I'd just like to hear it
said out loud.
( chuckles )
$1.4 million.
Donna:
Our base is loyal
and costs only rise
in success.
So our churn rate, page 25,
and our burn rate, 26,
are practically
nonexistent.
In its first year alone,
we believe Mutiny Exchange
will see upwards
of a half a million deals.
Today, we're offering you
the opportunity to make
the first one.
Told you, Mac.
You were right.
First-rate.
( clears throat )
Best I've heard in a while.
Why am I one
of the last to hear it?
Because we've been
assessing the VC
landscape--
I've heard you've been
up and down Sand Hill Road
with this.
Well, we're new in town.
We're hungry and we want
to move fast.
Okay, I get that.
Our portfolio
is 27 companies deep
as of Q2 '86.
We are in on 3Com
and Cisco and--
shit, Tim, that reminds me,
I gotta call Sandy back.
One of your best
was Oracle.
IPO'd last month,
two million shares,
$55 a pop.
Sure did.
Larry made us $55 million.
Are you telling me
you could do the same?
Well, lend us
1.4 of that 55
and we'll show you.
We've been burned
in the past.
We will throw
our hat in the ring
only to have
our offer shot up
and down the Valley.
I don't like games
and I don't want to be
used as a stalking horse.
If we were to move on this
and give you a term sheet,
we'd want a no-shop
in return.
We wouldn't be here
if we weren't ready
to do business.
Excuse me,
Mr. MacMillan, sir.
If I can have
a moment of your time.
Sir.
3,000 to one.
Those are the odds
of getting hit by lightning
in your lifetime.
They're also the odds
of getting hit by
a computer virus.
But in, like, five years,
those odds are gonna
go way up.
For-- for viruses,
not lightning.
But that's why your work
is so critical.
Because people
are focused on today
and you're already
into tomorrow.
- Do you have a name?
- Yeah, of course.
It's Ryan.
Ryan Ray.
Ryan, it's 52 degrees
in that water.
I'm gonna get into
some dry clothes.
I work for Mutiny
with Cameron Howe
and Gordon Clark.
MacMillan Utility
is basically Sonaris
virus with lipstick.
And only two KLOCs
out of 452 separate it.
And those two KLOCs
completely changed
the functionality
and purpose of
the entire program.
It's completely amazing.
And, you know,
I pulled it apart
in less than a day.
Trying
to impress me, Ryan?
Uh, yeah, that was
sort of the point.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah, sure, anything.
The Bay Area has 13 breaks
worth surfing.
How many did you go to
before you found me?
Honestly? Four.
11.
( engine starts )
( theme music playing )
12 days and the same old
song and dance.
He's still working on Mac.
Okay, so then Tim's
either full of shit
or he's got no juice.
Harpor was our last shot.
We've got a couple
more meetings, but they're
smaller boutique firms.
If we get denied first-round
funding across the board,
then it'll be impossible
to get that stink off
no matter what we do next.
I don't get it.
The idea is great.
The prospectus kicks ass
every meeting we've gone into.
14 VC firms and nobody's
stepped up, why?
Well, these clowns
love to make you wait.
They think it gives them
some kind of an allure.
But it just takes one of them
to ask you to the dance.
God, I love how even
the metaphors in this
business are sexist.
We can hit them
with all the data and
all the hard facts we want,
but the minute we walk in there,
they still see just one thing.
You guys can't take
this stuff so personally.
- But this company is us.
- Well, just give it time.
Bos, we haven't
heard back from a single
investor in weeks.
Bosworth:
What do you
want me to say?
Look, the fact that
you two are women I'm sure
doesn't help matters.
I think I liked it better
when you were lying to us.
These smiling VCs
out here love to grin
and screw you, don't they?
At least in Texas
they stab you in the front.
- ( knocks )
- What?
Tim Hankel
from Harpor Capital.
( clears throat )
Tim, hey, have you
heard from Mac yet
or do I have to keep
calling you until you take out
a restraining order on me?
- ( chuckles )
- Tim: Ha, I know, I know.
I'm sorry
it's taking so long,
but it was worth it.
We are a go.
I told you I'd get Mac on board
and I'm a man of my word.
He just got back from Aspen,
but he's off to LA tomorrow,
so he wants something
in place before he leaves.
You two free to talk
first steps tonight?
Yes, let me
check my schedule
and get back to you.
- ( laughs )
- ( cheering )
"So Sad" playing
♪ If you had
the right spot ♪
♪ And you can see
the sky... ♪
No, you can do that
without the GOTO statements.
And it's always better
without spaghetti branching.
Structured programing.
Bohm-Jacopini style.
Bohm-Jacopini.
You got it.
Yeah,
I'll write it down.
Walking the floor,
not really working,
wearing a tie.
You looking
to become management?
What?
No, no.
I got another bullshit
deposition today.
Going in tomorrow, too.
MacMillan lawsuit?
Yep.
That's three
already this month.
Dogget:
Is that intimidating?
Getting grilled
with Joe MacMillan
staring at you with
those eyes of his?
No, he's not there.
It's just me and
the lawyers.
More boring than brutal.
You know, they ask you
the same stupid questions
over and over,
hoping you'll slip up.
Give anything if it was
to be over so I can collect
the damn check already.
That'd be sweet.
Better brush the nacho dust
off your tie first.
( coders laugh )
Bosworth:
Okay, gentlemen.
Gentlemen, it's that time
of the week again.
- ( coders groan )
- Bosworth: I know.
I love it, too.
All right, I need
some clarification
on your supply needs
because, well,
there was a bit
of confusion last time.
After we made the deal
with Hayes for the 2400s,
I got on the phone with
the fella from Fulfillment
and he asked
if I wanted those
additional RS-232 cables
to which I,
per your wise
instruction, reply,
"No, sir, those are
not the droids that
I'm looking for."
( laughing )
So after he got done
laughing his ass off,
he explained that someone
must be messing with me.
Well done, boys.
I appreciate it.
Moving on.
All right, I need an update
on the graphics extension
for the Mutiny Exchange demo
y'all are working on
and how it will
interface with existing
neighborhood graphics.
We have the sprite engine
mostly working,
but we still have a problem
with the scan line rendering.
Yeah, we're getting
a tile map cache miss,
so we're losing
synchronization
on the palette.
Okay, well, hold it.
So is the thing
with the palette
connected to the--
- ( pounds table )
As I said last time...
- Hey.
...we should be using
a blitter on a bitmap
so we can do it in software
and not freeze out devices
that don't have support
for hardware sprites.
Okay, slow down.
Slow down. Are we
in agreement here?
You're talking
about a whole new
change of course.
Doesn't matter.
Just scribble down
what we say,
give it to Cameron,
she'll understand what
we're talking about
and stop wasting
our time.
You know, I'm not sure
I got all that.
See, sometimes
I'm a bit slow.
Need things repeated
to me twice.
Why don't you stand up
and say that to my face?
You want to stand
right up and repeat
that to my face, son?
Hey, Bos.
Bos, you got a sec?
Real quick.
Bos.
Hey, listen, look, I know
you hate these meetings.
Oh, yeah, compared
to a prostate exam, no,
I positively love them.
- Look, this is not
my forte, Gordon.
- I understand.
The girls got
their plates full,
but Cameron says,
- "Bos, you want to come in"--
- Okay, okay, let me run them.
Okay? I speak
their language,
so they can't mess with me
and it could be more efficient.
Look, I'm not trying
to step on your toes--
Wake me
if there's a problem.
- Gordon.
- Yeah?
Um, thanks for
having my back.
Yeah, sure.
Listen...
I know what it's like
to be the smartest
guy in the room
and I also know it's a waste
of time trying to prove it.
Let your work
speak for itself
and be open
to the possibility
that people that
don't understand you,
they're not necessarily
trying to get in your way.
How can I if no one
can see the work?
I have ideas.
Real ideas.
They might sound
theoretical,
but I can make
them happen.
I told Cameron and Donna,
but they didn't even listen.
They just had Bos
pay me to shut up.
What ideas?
"Bonna Rue" playing
Mac:
On the way back
to the lodge,
Dawkins says,
"Let's make snow angels."
He lies down in the snow,
sticks out his arms,
and then passes out
just drunk as a skunk.
We called him Snow Jesus
the rest of the trip.
( laughter )
Okay, glad you had
a good ski thing.
Tim said that you wanted
to discuss first steps.
- I want to level with you.
- Donna: Okay.
- I'm sure you heard about
AT&amp;T axing Viewtron.
- Oh, yeah.
Some folks in town
think that is the end
of online newspapers,
but I have got some insight
into what's really going on
over at Knight Ridder
and I think that
just real opportunity
is being vacated there.
Which means?
Which means I'm gonna
go in big on videotex.
It's gonna tie up
more of our capital,
which also means
I don't think I can do 1.4.
I'm sorry.
- Oh.
- Oh, so...
it's a pass, then.
No, hold on.
It's not that
black and white.
We still want you
in the portfolio.
Your concept has
just great potential.
And, honestly,
the two of you,
- really sharp.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, thank you, but--
- Tim, you want to walk
them through it?
Yeah, okay,
so we can't do 1.4,
but what if we aim
for a leaner, meaner
Mutiny Exchange?
- You mean cheaper?
- No, smarter.
Doing more with less.
Like, for instance,
I think you can make do
with half as many
new hires as you have
laid out in the prospectus.
Yeah, and I think you can skip
the server computer upgrades,
at least initially.
Less risk, more reward.
It's a surefire way to go.
- Does that sound good?
- You know, let's just
hold off on the--
just for a second.
What I'm hearing is that
you want to lock us up
by investing a fraction
of what we're asking.
No, you're misinterpreting
what we're saying.
Oracle was the same deal.
Investment grew over time.
It's how things
get done out here.
Okay, so then how much money
are you offering us?
Mac:
That is a number that we are
still trying to figure out.
That's what
this was all about,
getting the ball rolling,
assuming that
you are amenable.
Well, we've put a lot
of thought into this
and there really
isn't much fat.
Yeah, you know,
there's no fat.
Well, ahem, you two
are new to the Valley
and I know you want
everything that you want
right away.
But out here, funding
is like doubles tennis.
- Mm-hmm.
- You got to know who
you're partnering with.
- Mm-hmm.
- Can you trust each other?
Do you play well
together?
Is it a good fit?
And that's not easy to know
after just one meeting
or even over dinner.
Yeah, listen,
we both know that success
in this industry comes
down to timing.
We have to be first
to market,
and without
sufficient funding,
our ability to do so
is seriously compromised.
And then we all lose.
I hear that,
but let's just...
( exhales )
just take a beat,
enjoy our meal,
see how the evening goes.
And then maybe I will
look into cutting you
a good-faith check
in the morning.
( chuckles )
I'm gonna pop out
for a call.
Just think it over.
I thought this
was a serious meeting.
- We are serious.
- What the hell was that?
It was an opportunity
for you guys to jump to
the front of the line.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Wow, okay, my apologies
if he misread things.
What could he have
possibly misread?
We have been nothing
but professional.
Are you kidding?
You guys call every day
for two weeks.
You drop everything
the night he calls
you to dinner.
And I'm sorry,
but nobody wears
that shade of lipstick
unless they
have come to play.
We're going.
No, you know what?
I'm going to tell him---
- ( chatter )
- ( phones ringing )
Joe:
I want our discs
available beyond stores
aimed at the computer crowd.
What's the point
of making something free
if no one can find it?
Listen, be creative.
We're after first-time
PC users.
We should be
in grocery stores,
video stores, malls.
We want to be
everywhere they are.
I want people
sick of seeing us
the same way I'm sick
of seeing you. Go.
( keyboard clacking )
Joe:
Cynthia!
( door opens )
- Are you Ryan Ray?
- Yeah.
Mr. MacMillan
will see you.
Every day this week
at 9:00 A.M.,
I've got a meeting
scheduled with Ryan Ray.
How long
did this take you?
Two hours.
Okay, you're here.
You've gone to a lot
of trouble to be here.
You've got three minutes.
Okay, then I'll cut
to the chase.
I want to work
at MacMillan Utility.
Want is very different
than need.
- Okay, I need
to work here.
- Why?
Because I'm fascinated
by antivirus software.
I'm not.
It bores me.
Okay, um, because you set
the gold standard
and you're looking
for your next challenge.
- I am, too.
- What makes you think you
know what I'm looking for?
I don't.
Yeah, that was presumptuous.
Only you know that.
What makes you think
I know what I'm looking for?
Because you're brilliant.
Wait, don't you?
I mean, you don't
have to answer that.
Why would you? I
just--
Whatever you
want to do next,
I'm in.
This is a test
and that was the wrong
answer, right?
This is a test and that
was the right answer?
I don't know what
you want me to say.
Whatever you actually
came here to say.
I can't imagine
that I've heard it yet.
I feel like you're judging me.
It doesn't matter what I say.
Even when you're not talking,
you seem disappointed.
You could ask me
what color the sky is
and I would say blue
and somehow I'd be wrong.
You would be.
It's overcast.
You plucked Gordon Clark
out of obscurity, right?
He was nothing
before he met you.
I know him.
I work with him.
So you keep saying.
I'm just as good as he is
and a hard worker
with initiative.
I learned you surfed,
so I woke up at 5:00
in the morning
for two weeks straight
and cased 11 beaches
to find you.
I hacked
a security company.
Your security company.
Doesn't any
of that prove that...
Okay, this is gonna
sound weird
and I feel ridiculous
even saying this,
but I know
that something's coming.
Something big.
Like a train and all I want
is to jump on board.
But it's getting faster
and faster and I'm terrified
that I'm gonna miss it.
That night--
that night that you
spoke at the Castro,
I was like,
finally,
somebody sees
the world the way I do.
And I knew right then
that this was my ticket
on that train.
I don't know what else
to tell you, man.
I just want
to work with you--
need to work with you.
On anything.
Please.
Nobody listens to me.
No one takes me
seriously.
I don't want to get
left behind.
Your three minutes
are up.
You look great.
( door opens )
Mrs. Clark,
Miss Howe.
Follow me.
Thank you.
We're just going
right down there.
Oh.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
- Should we sit?
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Oh, Diane.
- Donna, hi.
Oh, my God,
I feel so stupid.
I had no idea
you were the Gould
in Amador Gould Gilson.
Small world.
Smaller valley.
But this is great.
Now we don't have
to waste time
exchanging pleasantries
or small talk.
- Except for...
- Yes, Cameron Howe.
Oh, Diane is a mom
at Joanie's school.
Okay.
Oh, wait, the mom
of the girl that
Joanie beat up?
I heard it was
more of a draw.
( laughs )
This is Elias Amador.
He'll be joining us.
Hello.
Full disclosure,
I haven't had time
to read this,
but love how you've
grown Mutiny and can't wait
to hear what you've got.
I can't tell you
what a nice change
this is,
pitching to
a familiar face
and Elias.
- Shall we just...?
- Whenever you're ready.
Imagine a place
you could go
where whatever your passion,
whatever you collect or love,
it's available to you
at the push of a button.
A rare Spider-Man comic,
a bootleg Dylan concert,
first edition Fitzgerald,
even a hard-to-find part
for your Apple II.
- It's all there.
- You don't have to scour
the local flea market.
On the chance that
they might have it.
- Or hit every garage sale.
- On the chance that they
might have it.
Or even leave your home.
Cameron:
Because you're connecting
to people across the country
- who are all part of--
- Let me stop you right there.
Everything you're saying
sounds terrific, but just
to cut to the chase,
you're shifting your core
business from chat
to trade, yes?
No, not shifting.
We're expanding.
And it isn't the first time.
We started with games.
We noticed that our users
were chatting during games,
so we moved into chat
and our base jumped
exponentially.
And then we noticed
that our users were
trading during chat,
so we go where the user
behavior takes us.
It's our business model
and it's proven to be
highly effective.
Right, just to be clear,
though,
your expansion is predicated
on the idea of swapping goods
through a BBS?
- Yes.
- Yes, exactly.
Elias, anything
you'd like to ask?
I'm good.
Thank you.
Okay, thank you
for coming in.
Our pleasure.
We'll look forward to--
But I'm afraid
it's a pass.
I'm sor--
I don't understand.
Don't you want to at least
look at the numbers?
No, sorry.
Okay, well, thank you
for your time.
Thank you.
- Thank you for coming in.
- Yeah.
Unbelievable.
So much for sisters
doing it for themselves.
Jesus, they say the next best
thing to a yes is a quick no.
You can't get
much quicker than that.
Yeah, well, that was
too goddamn quick.
It's like she made up
her mind when she saw
it was me.
No, she didn't.
Aaron:
Mr. Clark, you created
the Sonaris virus
that took down WestNet,
yes?
No, I created a fetch program
to detect network size.
Due to an error,
it self-propagated.
I had nothing to do
with it infecting WestNet.
But it's your contention
that the MacMillan
antivirus software
is a variation
of this fetch program?
No, no, it's not
a variation.
Only two kilo lines of code
out of 452 were changed.
I know this because
I changed them myself and
hand-delivered it to Joe.
Yes, he may have added
some bells and whistles
since then,
but, come on,
he's not fooling anyone.
Aaron:
When you say you
hand-delivered the program,
was that a gift
or a transaction?
Aren't gifts a type
of transaction?
You give a gift
to a friend.
You have a transaction
with a business partner.
Okay, did you
just make that up
or is that a real thing?
Mr. Clark, at what
address did you live
on the date
of July 30, 1985?
Same address that I lived at
on February 17, 1985,
and January 27, 1985,
and May 1, 1985,
and every other date
that you've asked me about.
Could you please
repeat the address?
2824 DePue Drive,
Richardson, Texas.
And did Mr. MacMillan
visit you
at your residence
at 2824 DePue Drive
on July 30, 1985?
Yes.
And how did he know that
you lived at said address?
Because he had
been there before.
And why had he
been there before?
Because we were
business partners.
And friends?
Yeah, and friends.
So, when he visited you
on July 30, 1985,
at 2824 DePue Drive,
was that as a business
partner or a friend?
I don't know.
You'd have to ask him.
From your perspective.
From my perspective?
From my perspective,
Joe MacMillan does things
for one reason
and one reason only
and th--
Hey, excuse me,
we are right--
We had an agreement
to keep these depositions
private, Mr. MacMillan.
Please,
finish that thought.
Because he's a selfish,
self-loathing, self-serving
piece of shit.
I'm prepared to offer
you 50% of my stake
in the company.
Aaron:
Mr. MacMillan,
this is completely--
Joe:
It's an even split.
I've got one condition.
I want you to come
run it with me.
Mr. MacMillan,
I'd really prefer that you
run something like this--
Aaron, it's fine.
60%.
70%.
Come be my partner
and 70% of the company
is yours.
Mr. Clark, my professional
advice would be to seriously
consider--
I'd like to state
for the record that this
is not a legitimate offer.
It's fully legitimate.
I'll sign anything you put
in front of me.
Just say the word, Gordon.
I don't want to work
with you, Joe.
I think we now know what
this lawsuit is really about.
Aaron:
Returning to the date
of July 30, 1985,
Mr. Clark, from your
perspective,
did Joe MacMillan
come to your residence
at 2824 DePue Drive
as a business partner
or a friend?
I have no idea.
Joanie:
What are we looking
for anyway?
A mistake.
My parents are up
in their bedroom
wrapping presents
for my birthday party.
Like I don't know exactly
what they're doing.
They still think
of me as little.
Well, it's 'cause
they've never seen you
throw back a whiskey
and smoke a cigar
like I have.
I never did that!
( chuckles )
You're joking.
I wish I didn't have
to have a birthday party.
I don't believe
in birthday parties.
You can do that?
Yeah, it's your birthday.
You can do whatever you want.
( sighs )
Did you find the mistake?
No.
So who's coming
to this stupid party
your parents are making you
throw that you don't really
want to have anyway?
Okay, let's take it
outside, okay?
All right,
everybody, let's move it
on out to the backyard.
Slip'N Slide is out there.
Let's go, let's go.
Everybody out.
Move it.
Get out of here.
Go. Go.
( doorbell rings )
Joanie, you've got
another guest to greet.
Joanie!
Oh, thank goodness.
( laughs )
Come on in.
Jennifer knew the name
of the street, but not
the address.
So we parked, prayed,
and followed the screams.
Donna:
I wasn't expecting you.
Diane: Joanie invited
Jennifer and seeing as how
I am her chauffeur,
we're part
of a package deal.
Where should I put this?
You know what?
The girls and the gift
table are all out back.
I cannot believe
she's here.
I guess Joanie patched
things up with Jennifer.
God, I'm telling you,
girls at this age,
it's crazy.
One day
they're mortal enemies,
the next day
they're best friends.
What?
Well, I mean,
she's here.
Should we take
advantage of it?
No, I don't want to face
that humiliation again.
"I Need That Record" playing
Daddy, Daddy!
Watch me!
Hey, Ryan,
you made it.
Yeah.
I can't stay long.
- Not that it's not
a nice party.
- Thanks.
I wouldn't know; I've never
been to a 10-year-old's
birthday party.
Well, not since
I was 10.
What do grown-ups do
at these things?
Oh, well, drink.
Hey, so--
so listen,
we're not supposed
to be talking shop today,
but I had a few ideas
on how to move your
chat idea forward.
Oh, yeah?
Really? How?
Yeah, well,
all right, listen.
A few years back,
CompuServe had this
CB Simulator
that I was totally
obsessed with.
We could start with that
as a rudimentary template.
My idea
is way more advanced
than CompuServe.
I know, I know.
All we would take
from CompuServe is--
is the shared memory
virtual array manager
from the CBSIM code.
We make it bigger
so we can support more users
and the rest
we build from scratch.
That would be
a time-saver.
Yeah, totally.
Come here.
No one designs
in a vacuum.
What's the point
in reinventing the wheel
if your true innovation
is creating the tire?
Yeah.
Take the Giant, okay?
Say what you will about it,
but I started with a IBM PC
and made something
that was twice as fast
at half the cost
and portable
at 15 pounds.
I thought
that was Joe MacMillan.
( coughs )
Joe MacMillan
might have pulled
the specs out of his ass,
but turning them
into a working product?
No, not really
his bag of tricks.
- Hey.
Howdy, Ryan.
Look at this.
- What you got there?
- Got it for Joanie.
- Robo Butler.
- That looks ridiculous.
Yeah, well, it ain't
your birthday, is it?
- What's it do exactly?
- Here, look at this.
( laughs )
Lookit here.
Come here,
let me show you.
Come on.
Look, all right, here.
Get your beers right there
into the metal paws. Come on.
If you got to put the beers
in his hands, why don't you
just take them with you?
I mean, what's the point
of having the robot
bring them to you?
'Cause he's a butler, man.
It's what he does.
- All right.
- Now back up.
Back up. Watch.
Joanie gonna love this.
Hey!
( laughs )
Look at him.
Come on there, butler.
Look at me,
I'm Robo Butler.
Would you gentlemen
care for more beers?
Bos, it's so slow.
I mean, look, it's taking
forever to get here.
I could've walked
over here faster.
- ( laughs )
- I got the receipt.
Don't give that
to Joanie, all right.
You're only gonna upset her.
She gonna love it.
Hey, nice to see Joanie
and Jennifer getting along.
Just so you know,
I get 60 proposals a week.
Most weeks
I pass on all 60.
It really had nothing
to do with you.
No, I completely
understand.
It was a really
quick no you gave us
in there, though.
All right, let's talk,
but not out here.
Are you laughing
at my butler, children?
Get out of here.
Scram, all of you.
- ( girls laughing )
- Get out of here.
Dang butler.
Oh, hell.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
I've been combing
over our prospectus,
replaying our meeting,
trying to figure out why
Elias's note derailed things.
I've narrowed it down
to three possibilities.
A: Elias doesn't believe
our user base will embrace
Mutiny Exchange as rapidly
as our projections,
which is wrong.
B: Elias thinks
our timeframe from
development to beta
is overly optimistic,
which is also wrong.
C: Elias is a sexist jerk
who doesn't believe two women
can run a company, which--
- Okay.
- I'm leaning towards C.
Elias is a sexist jerk,
but better than most.
He doesn't care who runs
a company as long as it
makes him money.
Okay, then I'm at a loss
because you're a smart woman
and Exchange
is a great idea.
I am smart
and it is a great idea.
And that's your problem.
You didn't allow for D.
Another company
is already doing this.
What? Who?
It's a small outfit
Elias has been tracking
as a potential investment.
SwapMeet.
It's a good name.
I wasn't aware of it.
Otherwise I never would
have had you come in.
What do you know
about them?
Only that they have
an 18-month head start.
( groans )
And at the end of the day,
that's what informed
our decision.
It made no sense
to bet on Mutiny
in a battle
you weren't just losing,
but didn't even know
you were fighting.
( girls laughing,
chatting )
Jennifer:
Hey, wait, guys,
do you want to come play?
Okay, let's play a game.
Hey, sweetie.
You doing okay?
Oh, she's really pulling
focus, isn't she?
Kind of like
it's her birthday
party and not yours.
Look, honey,
I just want you to know
how proud I am of you
for inviting Jennifer.
It shows real maturity.
- Okay.
- A birthday's
not just a party.
It's marking a passage
of time in your life.
You're showing me you're not
just a little girl anymore--
Okay, I heard you.
Growing up and you're
proud of me.
- Can we just
do the cake now?
- No, no. Come here.
I want to make sure
you hear what I'm saying.
Okay, you did a really
grown-up thing today
and your dad, he couldn't
be more proud of you than
he is right now.
Stop saying that.
Cameron paid me 20 bucks
to invite Jennifer to come.
Okay?
I hate Jennifer.
Can we just do
the cake now, please?
- Everyone's asking for it.
- Yeah, sure.
Let's do the cake.
Okay, I've been on Mutiny
asking around,
trying to figure out
what I could about
this SwapMeet.
- And?
- From what I can tell,
it sounds seriously
less robust than what we
have in mind for Exchange.
Plus, it's focused
on sports memorabilia,
so I just can't see it
reaching anywhere
near the size and scope
of our user base.
Hey, sure was weird
that Jennifer came to
the party, wasn't it?
Yeah. We will not lose
to an inferior product.
- I refuse to be Betamax.
- 'Cause I don't remember
inviting her.
Oh, no, we didn't.
Joanie did that all
on her own.
- Wasn't that mature of her?
- Yeah, it was.
It shows a hell of a lot
of maturity that she
would invite Jennifer.
Which, you know,
reminds me.
What?
What is this for?
For all your help today.
Okay.
Thanks.
Uh, I'll be in my room.
She went out
and grabbed some cups
for us at the party.
( phone rings )
Ryan Ray.
Joe:
Ryan.
Mr. MacMillan.
Ryan, I want you to do
something for me.
Um, okay.
What?
I want you to stand up.
I want you to take
a long look around.
I want you
to make sure you see
every single person
in that room.
- Are you doing that?
- Uh, yeah.
Good.
Now forget them,
because you don't work
with those people anymore.
I'll see you tomorrow
at my office, 9:00 A.M. sharp.
Oh, my God.
I'll be there.
Thank you.
Now, Ryan,
there's one more thing
I want you to do for me.
( elevator bell dings )
- Incredible.
- Look.
It's her.
Turn around.
Isn't this a bit
formal for us?
We could just meet
at Jennifer's birthday
party next month.
Oh, no, we'll just
be a minute.
I admire persistence,
I really do,
but we've been over this.
Even if I wanted to,
I couldn't convince
my partners to fund
your expansion.
- I'm sorry.
- No, we understand.
- That's not why we're here.
- No, because you're right.
SwapMeet is our competition.
It'd be foolish for you
to invest
over a million dollars just
to see if we can catch up.
And that's why
we've done our homework.
And what we found
is that while SwapMeet
does have
a functional program
that it would take us a year
or more to compete with,
what they don't have
is anywhere near the size
of our user base.
We don't want you to help us
compete with SwapMeet.
We want you
to help us buy them.
It's not a million
to fight a war,
it's a few hundred
thousand to win it.
( laughs )
Yes!
Oh, my God, I'm--
I'm so sorry.
( stall door closes,
locks )
Hey, Ryan.
Great news.
I tracked down
that CBSIM code,
so we can get
started today.
You know, just--
just you and me.
( sighs )
I'm going to work
for Joe MacMillan.
( music playing )