( static hissing )
CQ, CQ, is this
frequency in use?
( static hissing )
CQ, is anybody out there?
Hello?
This is KC4L.
Can anybody hear me?
( static hissing )
What's that?
Uh, it's a radio
that I made.
What does CQ mean?
It's what you say
when you're looking for other
people who've made radios.
Comes from the French
word sécurité,
which means safety
or security.
You can hear it when
you say "secu, secu."
Did you want something?
I wanted to say good night.
Oh, God, Lump,
I'm so sorry.
Did you brush your teeth?
Okay, I'll be out there
in just a second, okay?
Daddy's in the closet
looking for people
with radios.
Okay.
( blows )
( scoffs )
That thing made it
from Texas
and the KitchenAid
is still in storage?
Are you really
gonna stand there and try
and pass yourself off
as someone who ever
used that mixer?
Are you sure
this is the best place
for all this?
No, I'm pretty sure
it's the worst place
for it,
but since the place
that I was gonna use
isn't available,
- I'm making do.
- Okay, sorry.
Have you found anyone?
No, the connection sucks.
Is it the antenna, maybe?
I don't know.
Could be.
Or it could be
that all the guys that were
out there when I was a kid
are too busy
running companies
to have time for hams.
Yeah, or they moved online.
There must be some
new kids out there.
I'll be out in a sec.
( music blaring on headset )
CQ, CQ, for shit's sake,
is anybody out there?
Hey, Cameron and I decided to
have a weekly project meeting
to streamline
the SwapMeet integration
and we thought that you'd
be a valuable addition.
Yeah, sure.
If you want me there.
Yeah, we do.
Do you want me there
because you think I might
have something to contribute
or because you want me
to feel like I have
something to do?
How about just because
I respect your opinion?
'Cause I just don't
want you to feel like
I can't self-start
because I absolutely can.
No, of course you can,
but the coders look to you.
I feel like you could be
a valuable liaison.
And I want you there.
Okay. Yeah.
I'll be there.
Good.
You know I don't
really have a choice.
You're my ride.
"Absolute Beginners" playing
♪ There's nothing
much to take ♪
♪ I'm an absolute beginner ♪
♪ And I'm absolutely sane ♪
♪ As long
as we're together ♪
♪ The rest
can go to hell ♪
♪ I absolutely love you ♪
♪ But we're
absolute beginners ♪
♪ With eyes
completely open ♪
♪ But nervous
all the same ♪
♪ If our love song... ♪
- Mr. MacMillan. Hi.
- Ryan, welcome.
I didn't realize it was,
you know, gonna be such
a big party, so I...
That was very thoughtful.
Thank you.
This is really
a beautiful place you have.
- You know, it's dark.
- Mmm.
Can't really see
what everything
looks like,
but from what
I can tell, it's--
it's so...
Asian.
I'm glad you like it.
Yeah, it took me
a while to find it.
I don't really know
the city that well.
I grew up
in Burlingame.
It's not far.
Just-- yeah, we didn't
really get to come to
the city that much.
I really
do like it, though.
I mean, look at it.
It's just so...
Asian.
You sure do have
a lot of friends, huh?
I wouldn't really call
these people my friends.
Most of them
don't even know
whose house they're at.
Except for Ken over there.
Ken knows exactly
where he is.
You know what?
I'm thirsty.
Why don't we
open this up?
♪ As long as you're
still smiling... ♪
So whereabouts
do you live now?
Or are you still
in Burlingame?
Oh, no, I got out
of there a while ago.
I'm in Los Altos
now with a bunch
of college buddies.
They're really jealous
that I'm working for you.
I was telling them
about how the office
is on the top--
What do you do for fun?
Oh, um, you know,
the usual.
Video games.
Movies.
But mostly
I just love to code.
I can't tell you
how curious I am
to see what you have
in mind for me.
You came to me, Ryan.
Yeah, I know.
I have a ton of ideas.
I'd love to show them to you.
But I know the company
is focused on user version
2.0 right now.
So I'm just ready
to pitch in.
Is that what you think
I'm looking for?
All right, someone just
came in who I really
need to speak to.
Hey, it's a party.
Try and have fun.
♪ If there's reason ♪
♪ To feel
all the hard times ♪
♪ To lay down
the hard lines ♪
♪ It's absolutely true. ♪
( static hissing )
( man's voice,
indistinct )
( theme music playing )
What are you doing up?
( sighs )
Joe MacMillan?
Really?
Do you have any idea
what you're getting
yourself into?
Well, I was hoping
to learn something--
Look, I know you must
be feeling real special
right about now.
Joe's great at that,
but trust me,
he will burn you.
Look, I know I should
have probably talked
to you about it--
He did it to me.
He did it to Gordon.
Even Donna, the nicest
woman on the planet,
doesn't speak
to him anymore.
You think you're gonna
be any different?
I don't know, Cameron.
Listen, I get it.
Really, I do.
And I'm willing to give you
a pass just this once.
Come back to Mutiny.
Be a part of something real.
I don't even think
the guys would have me back.
Well, the guys will deal
if I tell them to.
What do you say?
Okay.
You just made
a really dumb call.
I told her you weren't home.
She wouldn't leave.
She was here
for like an hour
just staring.
Dude, where've you been?
I got hammered
and passed out at Joe's.
Oh, wow.
Hey, was that fun?
I don't know
what the hell it was.
Okay, that makes
absolutely zero sense.
Well, we thought it made
a lot of sense.
Well, you guys are
the heads of the company.
Of course you should
be the ones to bring
the offer over to SwapMeet.
Gordon, it's a formality.
Bos can do it.
It's not a formality.
It's about perception.
And the people that
you're buying, especially since
they're coming to work here,
need to view you and Donna
as the ones in charge.
Gordon, we've already met
with them a gazillion
times, okay?
We've had lunch.
We've had drinks.
They know we're in charge.
God, if I had it
my way, they'd just
send us the disks
and we could
call it a day.
Okay, look,
it's dropping off
an envelope.
You don't mind
doing it, do you?
Do you want to make it
sound any less important?
- I would be happy to do it.
- Thank you.
Okay, so the whole company
is gonna bend over backwards
because she can't
get over herself.
No, I don't think
it's a good idea for us
to go either.
The heads of the company
don't tender the initial offer.
We wait for the counter
and only get involved
when the real
negotiations begin.
That's how you show them
who's in charge.
Mm, okay.
Okay, up next,
how are we doing
on the speed of
the background graphics?
Well, we'll never get under
half a second at 2,400 baud.
We're gonna need
to use Huffman,
or even better,
Lempel-Ziv compressions
so we're not sending
all the bits through.
Okay, since when are we
doing a graduate seminar
on information theory?
Our guys can't handle that.
No, no, no.
That's smart not sending
all the bits through.
We preload the most common
backgrounds on the diskettes
users already have
and just send
the catalog numbers.
Okay, so just send
the index to the scene.
Okay, that's good.
I see that.
That's good, right?
No complex coding.
Well, you'll have a limited
set of images
and the user
will get tired of waiting
for the same-old same-old,
but, yeah, it's great
if that's what you guys
want to do. Great.
- Great.
So we will
preload the data.
Thank you.
And now for what I thought
was going to be
the only unpleasant topic
for this meeting--
evidently I was wrong--
replacing Ryan.
Oh, I went by
his house this morning.
He is not open
to coming back.
What?
You didn't harm him
in any way, did you?
No, he was fine
when I left.
I mean, he's a moron,
but he was ambulatory.
You know, I want
you looking for people
at that class tonight.
Oh, God.
Hey, look,
I'm already covering
for you at this lunch.
And don't complain about
being asked for by name
by the next generation
of coding talent.
You should be
very flattered.
Even if I find someone,
it's gonna take forever
to catch them up.
Ryan really understood the guts
of the neighborhood code.
And if we're gonna build out
SwapMeet alongside it,
we need someone
who really gets it.
Well, uh, who wrote
the original code
for that section?
- Tom did.
- Great, which one is Tom?
None of them.
He didn't make the trip.
- Why not?
- He just didn't.
- Okay, was it
a money thing or...
- No.
- Well, then get him back.
If you can't get Ryan,
getting the programmer
who originated the code
makes the most sense.
Look, Gordon, I said no.
Can we just drop it, please?
Why am I even
in this meeting
if no one's gonna listen
to a word I have to say?
We are listening.
We're simply disagreeing.
No, Donna,
you're disagreeing.
Because you are opining
on subjects
about which you do not have
all the information.
I am opining on subjects
on which I am fully informed.
No, Gordon,
you really aren't.
A lot happened while you
were off doing other things.
Oh, damn it, Donna.
You know what?
I screwed her once, okay?
Jesus.
Excuse me.
What the hell was that?
Please, like Cameron
doesn't already know.
The walls in our place
are so goddamn thin,
she can hear it
every time I take a shit.
I invite you
to a meeting and this
is the way you behave?
- What is wrong with you?
- I am sick and tired
of being punished.
Okay? I agreed to the move.
I bought the mainframe.
I fixed the mainframe.
I've let her live with us.
Everything I've been asked
to do, I've done.
I shut you down because Tom
is Cameron's ex-boyfriend.
So what?
So it's obviously
a sensitive subject
and I was trying
to steer you away from it.
So you thought my infidelity
would be a wonderful topic?
You brought that up.
While I was off
doing other things.
Like everybody in this room
doesn't know what that means.
- I was talking
about the mainframe.
- No, you weren't.
No, you weren't
and don't pretend
that you were.
It's always there, Donna.
Every time I look at you,
it's always there.
This is not something
to discuss here.
We'll talk about it
at home.
What's the difference?
Man on radio:
Hello?
Greetings from the ether.
Is anybody there?
I'm right here.
Can you hear me?
This is KC4L, over.
Hello?
I'm right here.
Can you hear me?
Right this way.
First time
dining with us?
No.
I wish.
- Oh, hello there.
- No, don't get up.
- ( both chuckle )
- Oh.
Sorry.
Where's Cameron?
Oh, she is preparing
a guest lecture she
is giving tonight.
She's so sorry
that she couldn't
make it.
We'll have to
soldier on without her.
May I get you something
from the bar?
You know what?
I will have a gin
and tonic, please.
- Very well.
- Thank you.
Nice choice.
( laughs )
And what's your excuse?
I just like
drinking at lunch.
( laughs )
So, the official SwapMeet
offer is happening today?
Yes, John Bosworth
is taking it over later
this afternoon.
- Exciting.
- Yeah.
Will he go over
with you and Cameron?
No, he's our advance man.
He's taking care of it.
- Whenever the ladies are ready.
- The usual, Jason.
Chicken paillard.
It's thin, crispy,
and somehow still juicy.
I don't know
how they do it.
Uh, you know,
I will try the...
mushroom ris--
risotto.
You still wear
your ring, huh?
- For work.
- Mmm.
Men can't seem
to handle the idea
that sexual availability
and business acumen
can exist in the same body.
It simplifies things.
So when you say John Bosworth
is your advance man,
what exactly do you mean?
"War Songs" playing
♪ I like new fashion ♪
♪ I like old stories ♪
♪ Like my sister
used to tell ♪
♪ This is the voice ♪
♪ This is the picture ♪
♪ I like romantics,
but I don't like Steven ♪
♪ Old men... ♪
Whatcha doing?
Oh, I'm just working
on 2.0 with Brent.
I figured it was
all hands on deck,
so I would jump in
and help out.
Don't do that.
I've already got a Brent.
That's not what
I hired you for.
Hey!
Excuse me.
Wait.
Hey, man, why did you
hire me, then?
I'm beginning
to wonder that myself.
♪ Old men love
war songs ♪
♪ Love Vera Lynn... ♪
You know, I just--
I didn't know what
I was getting myself into.
You know, and I wanted
to fix things so bad,
but, I don't know,
she just doesn't seem
to want me there.
I mean,
she says she does,
but that's what she thinks
I want to hear.
( door opens )
Oh, wait.
- ( door closes )
- Donna?
That's my wife.
This is KC4L signing off.
Hey, Donna.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey.
I, uh, finally got
the ham working.
You know
I was always planning
on moving out, right?
Like, this is not exactly
an ideal setup for me either.
It's not like
I like listening
to you take a dump.
You know, just for
the record, Donna never
said anything to me
about whatever problems
you guys were having.
She would never do that.
( door closes )
( scraping )
( German accent )
I have the letters
of transit.
A very important
document.
- It's the SwapMeet offer.
- Oh.
And Godspeed to you, sir.
How was lunch?
Extremely delightful.
I had risotto,
which is rice,
but not.
( laughs )
What else did you have?
I had a few--
several gin and tonics.
- You okay?
- Yes, I'm great.
Fine.
You know, my ex worked
those long-haul flights
and I was away on business
half the month.
We barely spent
any time together.
Still managed to get
on each other's last nerve.
I don't know how
you and Gordon do it.
Well, apparently,
not so well.
I think your husband's
all kind of tricky,
but, by God,
I know he cares.
I can feel it
from 50 paces.
There are men
out there who've done
a lot worse, Donna.
Yeah.
But it's hard
to turn that
into good news.
I want you to come
to this meeting.
- Right now?
- Right now.
( door opens )
You must be
John Bosworth.
Diane Gould.
I'll be your backup
this afternoon.
Oh, pleasure
to meet you.
Didn't know
I needed backup.
Well, you don't,
of course.
I just knew you'd be here
and I thought it would be
a nice way for us to meet.
Sure.
Seems a little quiet.
Yeah, I noticed that.
And the parking lot
seemed empty.
Yeah, I noticed
that, too.
Maybe we should
get a tour.
We're giving them 600,000
of my hard-earned dollars
and a piece
of your company.
That earns us
a poke around.
Doug Sheridan.
So nice to meet you.
- Hey.
- This is my partner
Craig Bausch.
Craig, John Bosworth.
Nice to finally put
some faces to the names.
This here is Diane Gould,
our partner.
Of course.
Pleasure to finally
meet you.
This is quite
the delivery committee.
While we're here,
we thought we should
have a look around.
Oh, of course.
Sure.
Welcome.
( chuckles )
We pulled a pretty epic
all-nighter last night,
so we're kind of down
to bare bones.
But you should be able
to get a sense of the place.
( sips )
I know I speak
for all the investors
when I say
how delighted we are
with the growth
of the individual user base.
That tastes terrible.
- I mean, that tastes
just like... ugh.
- ( men laughing )
Look, we may not have
seen it at the start,
but the people
have spoken
and you truly are
the thought leader
that we always
knew you were.
Huh?
So 2.0.
When are we doing this?
Well, production can
have disks ready to ship
in a matter of months.
Man: The question is,
is it better to start charging
at the beginning of the year?
Man #2:
Or do we flip the switch
in September
and hope that the charges
get lost in the list of
back-to-school expenses?
What do you think?
When do you think
we should start charging
for the new user version?
Well, I--
I mean, I thought
you weren't going to charge.
( laughs )
Hold on, I'm--
I'm sorry,
what's your name again?
- Ryan.
- Ryan, right.
Of course
we're gonna charge.
I mean, what's the point
of developing a user base
if we don't turn them
into paying customers
at some point?
And my gut is telling me
sooner rather than later.
What a surprise.
I see a spigot
and I want to turn it on.
Man #2:
The focus groups
we've done indicate
we'll be losing
30-40% of our users
whenever we do it.
It's just a matter
of how big you want to grow
the base beforehand.
Man: And, unfortunately,
people are going to hate you
for a little while.
Sorry,
couldn't be helped.
Well, it's been a long time
since I cared what people
thought about me.
My gut says...
September.
What's our price point?
Man #2:
If we can stay below
the $15 threshold,
consumers seem willing
to shine it on.
Man:
Oof, that sounds awfully high.
Can't we keep it under 10?
Man #2:
No, the fact is for a one-time
annual expense of this kind--
$14.95.
Yes. That.
That right there.
That--
that has my vote.
Yes, please.
What do you think?
Yeah, I-I guess
$14.95 sounds good.
Well, if Ryan's
on board, huh?
So that's it.
Come September,
we start charging $14.95.
( door opens )
- You okay?
- Yeah, of course.
Look, I know
it tastes bad,
but this is
the right move.
- Mmm.
- I promise you,
all right?
( door closes )
( knocks )
Gordon:
Can I come in?
What is it?
Hey, I--
I just wanted to say
that even though it does
make perfect sense
to hire the person
who wrote that code,
I didn't realize that
that was someone that
you had a thing with.
So if I seemed insensitive
earlier today,
I'm sorry.
Okay.
And just--
Tom and I wrote
that code together.
Just, you know, FYI.
It wasn't all him.
Okay.
And I hope I didn't
make you feel
like you living here
is the cause of all
of our problems.
You're not gonna
start talking to me
about your wife, are you?
No, I'm not.
Just 'cause I really--
I don't think I can
handle that.
Look,
I still don't think
that we should all be living
under the same roof,
but obviously there's
something else going on.
That's all
I wanted to say.
So when are you guys
moving out?
( both laugh )
Jesus, you got
every goddamn mug
in the house in here.
No, I don't.
All right.
Hey, good luck tonight.
You, too.
I just don't understand
how the wind gets into
Candlestick.
- I mean, there are walls.
- ( Doug laughs )
Wind's a Giants fan.
It does what it
needs to do.
It beats the hell
out of sweating bullets
in Arlington.
Yeah, well, that's why
I'm a Houston fan.
Air conditioning
like God intended it.
Where was God
when Nolan Ryan
left that one
hanging for Will Clark
the other day?
( phone ringing )
You want to get that?
No, it's fine.
This is more important.
( ringing continues )
Yeah, hey, we appreciate
the extra attention,
but don't you fellas
have a receptionist?
Of course we do.
She's at lunch.
- Late lunch.
- We do a lot of business
with the East Coast.
So we work through
lunch a lot and then we,
you know, have it later.
Can somebody answer
the goddamn phone?
Everybody's really
spent from last night.
It was a real ball-breaker.
Yeah.
Sure.
What'd you do that for?
Oh, I'm not
comfortable with it.
No, it was a figure
that was arrived at
when we were operating
with less than current
information.
The value
of our company is in our
intellectual property,
our loyal customers,
it's not out there.
No, it sure
as hell isn't.
Come on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where are you going?
Oh, we need
to reassess.
Mr. Bosworth,
I assure you the company
you're bidding on
is a lean, mean
version of itself.
Oh, I'd say
it's a lean, mean version
worth about 400K.
400,000 sounds like
a good place to start.
No, it sounds
like a good place
to finish, son.
If you can find someone
willing to pay north of 350,
you should go for it.
- Wait, he just said 400.
- Oh, I'm sorry. My mistake.
- 325, how's that sound?
- ( phone ringing )
We just saved you
$250,000.
I'd think
you'd be happier.
I am happy, very.
I'm just
a little surprised
by how completely
off-book you went.
I thought this was
supposed to be handshakes
and how do you dos.
You see an opportunity,
you take it.
That's the sport of it.
It could have gone
the other way.
But it didn't.
( engine starts )
- ( knocks )
- Mr. MacMillan?
Uh, I just wanted
to say that--
that I don't think you should
charge for the user version.
Why didn't you say that
in the meeting?
I've been here
for, what, a week
and you plunk me down
in some senior staff meeting.
What was I supposed to say?
I just agreed with
everyone else.
But that's not right
because it's not
what I think.
I'm sorry you couldn't
keep up in the meeting.
You made a promise
to people that you
wouldn't charge them.
I didn't promise
that I wouldn't ever
charge them.
Of course you did.
You said freedom
from fear is a right
and you shouldn't
have to pay for it.
And in a perfect world
that would be true,
but it's not the world
we live in.
- Then why'd you say it?
- Because I believe it.
But I've got a board
and investors
and I've got people
to answer to.
But you're ruining
the product.
I am the product.
I know.
"The Boy in the Bubble"
playing
♪ It was a slow day
and the sun was beating ♪
♪ On the soldiers
by the side of the road ♪
♪ There was a bright light ♪
♪ A shattering
of shop windows ♪
♪ The bomb in the baby carriage
was wired to the radio ♪
♪ These are the days
of miracle and wonder ♪
♪ This is
the long distance call ♪
♪ The way the camera
follows us in slo-mo ♪
♪ The way we look
to us all ♪
to a distant constellation ♪
♪ That's dying
in a corner of the sky ♪
♪ These are the days
of miracle and wonder ♪
♪ And don't cry, baby,
don't cry, don't cry ♪
♪ It was dry wind ♪
♪ And it swept across
the desert ♪
♪ And it curled into
the circle of birth ♪
♪ And the dead sand
falling on the children... ♪
Cameron:
No, I was
at Austin Tech.
I never really finished,
but then I started working
and there was just
no real time to go back.
Man:
Thanks again for coming.
Yeah.
Feel free to start.
( engine stops )
What, no kiss
this time?
What do you want?
You gonna tell me
I'm a horrible person?
Go ahead.
I'd be well within
my rights to want that.
What I'd really
like to say is--
is thank you.
Really?
For what?
Everything,
I guess.
How could I have
risen from the ashes
if you hadn't burned
it all to the ground?
Is that why you stole
my best coder?
Who, Ryan?
Come on.
The Valley
is crawling with Ryans.
No, actually,
he's incredibly talented.
Do you want him back?
What are you doing here?
Did you follow me here?
No, Cam, I don't have
time to follow you.
I'm a--
I'm a student.
( laughs )
Why is that funny?
Because it's a lie.
Well, maybe I got tired
of being told
I was just a salesman
who couldn't code.
Okay.
I--
God, I don't know
what kind of dress-up
game you're playing,
but, yes,
you're a student.
I might not ever
be great at it, but...
I'm not unteachable.
Joe,
I know you got this
whole humble Zen master
thing working for you,
but come on.
Save it.
I'm not buying it.
You don't have
to buy it, Cam.
Haven't you heard?
I'm giving it
away for free.
( clicking )
Bosworth:
Cam.
How were they
last night?
I didn't see them.
They were in their room
when I got home and gone
before I left this morning.
It was quiet.
Yeah, that's not always
a good sign.
Well, it's better
than screaming.
I've heard quiet
make you beg for screaming.
"Leaving You" playing
- Put that there.
- ( clears throat )
Hey.
I want to apologize
for my outburst yesterday.
It was totally
inappropriate.
And it shouldn't
have happened.
So if I made anyone
feel uncomfortable,
then I'm sorry.
Well, that little speech
made me very uncomfortable.
- I'm kidding.
- It never happened.
- Come on.
- What?
- It so clearly did.
- It's a thing you say.
Okay, look, we don't have
to discuss this ad nauseam,
but we thought
saying nothing
seemed equally stupid.
So we're saying something.
We are aware that bringing
a marriage into the workplace
is complicated
and we're doing
the best we can, okay?
Now, can we try to get
back to where we were?
Okay, great.
The big Ryan-shaped hole.
Did you find
any prospects last night?
No, but I decided
we don't need anyone.
- Of course we do.
- No.
Not if I do it.
Oh, I don't know.
I feel like you're
already spread pretty thin.
No, he was right.
Getting the person
who originated the code
makes the most sense.
That's me.
Well, but you should
have some help.
We just bought a company.
Maybe one of them can help.
No! Look, I'd just have to
explain everything to them.
It makes double
the work for me.
All right, if you think
you can handle it.
Yes, I can.
Okay, so we got a call--
You got to be kidding me.
You're moving on?
Yes.
Did you have something
you wanted to say?
No. No, no, go ahead.
It's your meeting.
- We got a call--
- She can't do it herself.
The company spends
a third of its time
waiting for her as it is.
He's not wrong.
You could do a bit
more delegating.
I do, just not when it's
something that I think
is truly foundational.
But you think
that everything
is foundational.
Look, if she says
she can handle it,
she can handle it.
Oh, my God.
Gordon, what is
your argument?
You're just
sinking the company
by taking on all these--
- No, she's not
sinking anything.
- Can we please just focus?
( overlapping arguing )
I want you
to pack up your stuff.
Starting tomorrow,
we'll be working
out of my place.
If we're not charging
for 2.0,
we've got to find
a new income stream.
Don't smile.
We might fail.
"Burning Down the House"
playing
♪ Ah, watch out ♪
♪ You might get
what you're after ♪
♪ Cool babies ♪
♪ Strange
but not a stranger ♪
♪ I'm an ordinary guy ♪
♪ Burning down
the house... ♪
( music playing )