( music playing )
( beeps )
Jesus.
( chatter )
( fizzing )
Doug:
Your code loops
all over the place.
It's not structured.
It's not maintainable
by anyone.
- I disagree.
- There are reentrant forks,
no way of knowing
which branch invoked
a function.
We don't do that in C++.
It's officially deprecated
in the language.
I can maintain it.
There are condition
flags for everything.
There's no one-way arrow.
Is that what
you want to do?
Be the code grunt
for this sick piece
of choss?
Dougie, chill.
My guys will flowchart it.
I'll write out the flags...
I'm sure you will.
The flow chart
would strangle us.
It's a mess.
And what do you mean
your guys?
It's fast and it fits.
It's no longer necessary.
Doug, we bought
your company.
You should adapt
to our programming language.
I know it sucks
to be rewritten.
It doesn't make sense.
It's like asking a race car
to adapt to a covered wagon.
- Poetic.
- Maybe we should
all try to,
you know,
take our egos out of it.
Well, my ego would love
to have a good night's sleep,
but sadly it has
to rewrite your code first.
( pencil clatters )
Yikes.
Diane, I am so sorry.
Diane:
It's all fun and games
till someone gets
stabbed in the cheek.
Hi.
I'm just here to observe.
Okay, well...
I think we're all
on the same page now.
Definitely.
Um, we're really close.
( scoffs )
Maybe this'll help.
It's an integration
road map.
Look, we think the way you
created Mutiny was brilliant.
The original block of code
was truly innovative.
Mm-hmm, but?
It doesn't play nice
with our SwapMeet code.
If you make some changes
to that block
and we make
some changes to our C++...
It's a bug factory.
The old code makes
it impossible
to keep track
of the reentrant looping.
But I don't need
the object-oriented
language, okay?
I can keep track
of the looping in my head.
Oh, I get it.
You're that good.
Yeah, I am.
Aren't you?
Bosworth:
...looking all around
and then
he came around the side
of the trailer there.
And I swear to God,
he goes,
"Man, that ain't no bear.
That's your ex-wife."
- Grr!
- ( laughs )
- She was just doing
the whole thing.
- Uh-oh.
Oh, you surprised
to see her?
- Yeah.
- Mm-mm.
Adios, amiga.
- Hey there.
- Hi.
Hi.
( stammers )
Here, go ahead.
After you.
Thank you.
( chuckles )
Good day, ladies.
Donna:
Hi. Well, this is
a nice surprise.
I was in the neighborhood.
So, how's it going
with the SwapMeet guys?
Um, good.
You keep
telling me that
on the phone
with that same
not-so-sure thing
you do with your voice.
What not-so-sure thing?
( chuckles )
Anyway, I just popped
into their project meeting.
The vibe
was pretty hostile.
Why haven't you told me?
Well, it's a work
in progress.
- Donna.
- ( sighs ) I know.
Cam isn't comfortable
with the guys yet,
and I'm working on it.
- How are you
working on it?
- Well--
My point is,
we should be
working on it.
If there are issues,
we need to air them out.
Otherwise
resentment festers
and the whole thing
starts to rot.
All right,
how about this?
We could all
go to dinner tonight,
have some wine,
talk things through.
- I do like wine.
- Great.
But I can't do tonight.
I've got tickets
to a charity thing,
a fundraiser
for Save the Bay.
- Oh, that sounds--
- Terrible.
I was gonna say lovely.
My date just cancelled
and I have a plus one.
I could check with Gordon,
see if he could watch
the girls tonight.
No, um...
I was thinking
about John Bosworth.
Oh.
I mean...
really?
Bosworth:
"Man, that ain't no bear.
That's my ex-wife."
- ( all laugh )
- Grr!
You know, there'll be
a whole slew of Valley
big shots there.
It's a great opportunity
for John to make some
business connections.
Sure.
But...
nobody
calls him John.
I do.
"Never Get Older" playing
All right, guys.
Guys.
- Guys, please, please!
- Shh!
Bodie:
Yo, shut up, kid!
All right,
I know we've gotten off
to a rough start,
and I'm sorry about that.
That's the understatement
of the century.
We're in a bit
of a holding pattern
ever since Cam took over
for our lead coder.
- Louis: Yeah, that was genoid.
- Bodie: You don't know
jack about it.
But we're gonna use this
as an opportunity.
Now, I know we've
had some success
flowcharting
the two systems.
How are we doing
with our organizational
training objectives?
Oh, you mean
the buddy system?
It's a nightmare trying
to train these jokers.
All they want to do
is bitch about C++.
( robotic voice )
C++.
He just follows me
around all day doing
this idiotic routine.
- C++.
- Carl, he's
your trainee, okay?
- I don't care.
- Master Carl,
I've been programmed
- to observe
your every move...
- Okay.
...so I may learn
from your flawed behavior
what it is to be human.
Shut up,
shut up, shut up!
Bodie:
He's not even funny.
Bodie, stop
antagonizing him, okay?
- Beep-boop-beep.
- Get out of my face!
- Hey!
- Whoa, whoa!
Let's kill
these a-holes!
- Calm down!
- All: Oh!
Oh, shit.
You okay?
Everyone, sit down.
What the f--?
( theme music playing )
You see?
It is just so charming.
It has all
the original molding.
And all
the original mold.
And the backyard is adorable.
It's perfect for barbecues.
Oh, did you hear that?
Okay, why don't I give you
and your, uh, friend
a minute to talk?
Thanks.
She thinks we're a couple.
You're not my type.
Yeah, this place
has character.
This isn't a generic box.
No, the Mutiny house
had character.
This place
is just quaint.
You've hated
every place we've seen.
So? I'm picky.
And nothing feels right.
Is this about the house
or is this something else?
It's Thing One
and Thing Two.
God, I can't
stand them.
Especially the bigger Thing,
this arrogant frat boy.
( whines )
The smaller Thing's
not so bad.
You know their names.
Yes, Tweedledee
and Tweedledum.
Heckle and Jeckle.
Frick and Frack.
I get it.
But they want
to be useful.
By what? Translating
everything into C++?
Donna, if I knew
that was the plan,
I wouldn't have signed on.
But we did sign on.
The guys are under
a two-year contract
with a piece of the company.
We married them.
We have to sit down
and talk it out
before the whole thing
festers and rots.
- We're having dinner
tomorrow night.
- What?
That's a horrible idea.
Who suggested that?
I did.
Oh, great.
And so now you're
just informing me.
See?
It already
feels like home.
MacMillan Utility
was always intended to be
a jumping-off point.
Totally.
It's all about
transformation.
Many companies
start doing one thing
and then change direction.
If we can just find
the right vector.
Ryan:
Then our freeware
can stay free.
Router tech is promising.
Ah, Cisco's already
way ahead on that one.
Uh, 3-D graphics.
Uh, AI.
- 5th gen systems.
- It's a billion-dollar
road to nowhere.
I give it a year.
Fairchild made cameras.
Now they make semiconductors.
Coleco was the Connecticut
Leather Company.
Now they make video games.
Yeah, and Mutiny started
as a games company.
- Shut up.
- Sorry, I'm just
so stoked
to be a part
of your process.
- Plus the caffeine...
- No, I mean be quiet.
Now.
Please.
Shh.
Uh...
okay.
Let's circle
the five best ideas.
Wait, what--
what are you doing, man?
We spent weeks on that.
There's some
good stuff there.
Good is the enemy of great.
If anything's worth pursuing,
we'll remember it tomorrow.
( sighs )
"Beyond Belief" playing
♪ History repeats
the old conceits ♪
♪ The glib replies,
the same defeats ♪
♪ Keep your finger
on important issues ♪
♪ With crocodile tears
and a pocketful of tissues ♪
♪ I'm just the oily slick ♪
♪ On the windup world
of the nervous tick ♪
♪ In a very
fashionable hovel ♪
♪ I hang around,
dying to be tortured ♪
♪ You'll never be alone
in the bone orchard ♪
♪ This battle with the bottle
is nothing so novel ♪
♪ So in this almost empty
gin palace... ♪
( knock on door )
♪ Through a two-way
looking glass... ♪
Come in...
if you must.
Can we talk
for a minute?
I guess.
Look, I know we got off
on the wrong foot.
I mean, we all want
the same thing, right?
Yeah.
Maybe we...
got into this
too quickly,
but, yeah, let's--
we're in it now, so...
If you think
it was too quick,
you have your man
Bos to thank.
- He strong-armed us
into taking the deal.
- Really?
- 'Cause I heard that you
and Greg misrepresented...
- It's Craig.
...the value of your company
to lure us into overpaying.
What's your deal?
Why do you have
such a hard time
playing with others?
Were you born this way
or did some loser ex-boyfriend
turn you into
a man-hating bitch?
( phone ringing )
- Cameron: Ah!
- ♪ I've got a feeling ♪
♪ I'm gonna get
a lot of grief... ♪
- ( music stops )
- ( ringing continues )
What?
Man's voice:
Catherine? Is that you?
- Yes.
- It's Len.
What's wrong?
Nothing, just--
sorry to call you at work.
I wanted to let you know
your mom...
What?
Your mom and I
are selling the house.
Bought a little condo
outside of Miami.
We gotta get rid
of all that crap
in the garage.
Do-- do you want
your dad's stuff?
Your mom saved it for you,
but, you know, Miami.
We're gonna sell
everything that's left
over 4th of July weekend.
I was hoping you might
come and take a look,
say hello to your mother.
It's not like
it used to be.
She's much better now.
Oh, uh...
then why didn't
she call?
I hope you're doing well
out there.
I'll let your mom know
that we talked.
( line clicks,
dial tone )
( indistinct arguing )
Craig:
You need to apologize.
All you have to do
is say, "I'm sorry,"
that's it.
How many times
have I gotta try?
- God.
- Wait, Doug!
( door opens, closes )
Hey, what was that about?
Oh.
Oh, just
the usual ups and downs
of a magical partnership.
You're here late.
But then you're probably
always here late.
Are you implying
that I don't have a life?
Yes.
You could say
that Doug and I have
different styles.
No shit.
He just walked into my office
and called me a bitch.
( sighs )
I am so sorry.
Look, we're really excited
to be part of Mutiny.
It's just SwapMeet
was our baby.
I think Doug
still feels down
about having to sell.
But that's no excuse.
You want to see
something cool?
Is it a dead body?
Only if Doug's still here.
You sure this is okay?
He won't mind.
Can I ask you something?
Okay.
Why won't you change
that original block of PL/M?
It's the only piece left
that I wrote by myself.
Alone in my bedroom,
just me.
Back when this whole place
was just me.
I did all the timings
by hand,
I checked the status
on every buffer
and every keystroke
every time,
all with check loops.
It was fast
and it was...
Beautiful.
It is beautiful.
Yeah.
And what do you
want me to say?
I-- I'm proud
of this place.
But back then,
it was this secret.
It was all mine.
Then we should
leave it alone.
Ah.
( sighs )
Just got the weirdest
phone call.
My stepfather.
I guess he and my mom
are moving to Florida.
They're selling
all my dad's stuff.
He died when I was nine.
Shit.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Just he had
this motorcycle...
an old Panhead Harley.
Oh, he used to ride me
to school on it.
I'd show up to kindergarten
with this, like,
gigantic helmet.
I'm sure it looked
ridiculous, but it was--
it just felt so...
You should
go get the bike.
Have you ever considered
a solo business venture?
( soft laugh )
- ( gunshots )
- ( quacking )
( game chiming )
Hmm.
Wasn't the Nintendo system
supposed to be for Joanie?
- ( gunshots )
- No, it was a family present.
Anyways, I had to unwind
after that brawl today.
I honestly don't know
what to do about those guys.
Cardiff had its challenges,
but no one ever
punched me in the ear.
Yeah, well, you're not
at Cardiff anymore.
( gunshots )
There's your answer.
Just take the guys
out back and shoot 'em.
( quacking )
( chimes )
Bosworth:
Well, he comes around
the side of the trailer,
and he goes,
"Man, that ain't a bear.
That's your ex-wife."
- Grr!
- ( laughing )
See?
Thank you,
thank you.
( coughs )
Man, it was crazy, man.
And I don't know
how long she stayed there.
She was there all night,
just sort of
frozen in place.
Grr!
The poor bastard...
( woman giggles, screams )
( continues indistinctly )
- ( music playing )
- ( chattering )
Don't move.
Joe MacMillan.
Of course.
Diane Gould.
Funny that we've
never officially met.
But I'm certainly
aware of you.
Amador Gould Gilson.
I admire your business model.
Small, intelligent
investment portfolio.
I guess you could
call that boutique.
Well, size isn't
everything, right?
I hear you facilitated
the SwapMeet acquisition
at Mutiny.
Congrats.
We're very excited
about it.
I'm surprised Cameron Howe
wanted to play ball
with another company.
She must be
in a good place.
Excuse me.
Can I, um--
- can I borrow you
for a sec?
- Yeah.
It's great
to finally meet you.
Mm, you as well.
( whooping, giggling )
- ( music continues )
- ( chatter )
How do I get
one of these?
Uh, make more money.
Which brings us
to our little problem.
You heard
of this individual,
Topher Erickson?
Does not ring a bell.
His father's Cal Erickson,
senior vice president
of General Atomics.
Okay.
Well, apparently
he was at one
of your parties
and indulged in
a copious amount
of cocaine.
Mm-hmm.
And then grabbed
someone and went off
on a little joyride
in the brand-new Ferrari
his father procured for
his 18th birthday.
What kind of jerk
spends 60 grand
and buys Italian?
Yeah, well,
this particular jerk
funds about a quarter
of your business.
Hmm, okay.
And it's boring old
contractor clients like that
that float your little
software experiments.
I'm gonna mingle.
Set something up.
I'll do damage control.
Good.
- Hi there.
- Mm.
Friendly fella.
Well, we can't all have
your Southern charm.
I want to thank you
for calling me
when my grandson
was born.
That was you, right?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, sure.
Joe MacMillan,
man of mystery.
Yeah, it's always
good to hear from
an old... friend.
Well, you seem
to be doing just fine
making new friends.
Oh, Miss Gould is just
a business associate.
Oh, no, I mean
everyone here.
They're lapping you up.
It's a good call,
playing up the Texas thing.
People love
a performance.
It looks like you're
in a performance
of your own, huh?
More of a one-man show
kind of thing.
Yeah, I'm a regular
Spalding Gray.
I left someone hanging.
Be well.
Oh, good,
you're still here.
I was worried
you got kidnapped
by that old pal
Joe MacMillan.
- Can I top you off?
- Yes, please.
You certainly
made a splash tonight.
How so?
You're the life
of the party.
Everybody loves you.
Between you and me,
I told Donna
I was inviting you
for business.
But really, I just didn't
feel like flying solo,
you know,
under the circumstances?
Glad I could be
of service.
Isn't that crazy?
That you can build a life
with someone, raise kids,
spend your 20s, your 30s,
half your damn 40s together,
and in the end
feel nothing?
How is that possible?
I don't know.
Would you like
a cigarette?
No.
No, I'm good.
Somewhere along the line,
I lost my taste for tobacco.
And champagne.
Parties.
I told my lawyer
I didn't want
to fly up here
and bail Topher out
right away.
Let him cool
his heels for a while,
reflect upon
his actions.
Plus, SF's not
my cup of tea.
It must be hard
to leave La Jolla.
I love Del Mar.
It's got the perfect mix
of sand bottom beach breaks
and patchy reefs.
It's, uh--
it's very easy
to find a wave
you can call your own.
I've always envied surfers.
We do a little naval work
out at Coronado Island.
- Mm.
- Those bastards offshore
look like they don't have
a care in the world
while I'm stuck to my seat
worrying about packet switching
and computer viruses,
thank you very much.
- ( chuckles )
- Packet switching?
- Is that with the DoD?
- Yeah, nothing sexy.
Just moving a bunch
of electronic boxes around.
- Mm.
- System's so damn clunky,
they're gonna overhaul
the whole thing.
Ken:
Ugh, sounds like
a pain in the ass.
You know
what you should do?
You should take a page
from those carefree bastards
and you should
catch a wave, huh?
Clear your mind.
Joe's got
a great instructor
down your way.
She's, uh--
she's amazing.
And guess what,
her name--
it's, uh--
her name is Sandy.
- ( both laugh )
- Sandy.
- Right, Joe.
- ( chuckles )
That's good.
Love to meet her.
Look, I know
I'm being managed here.
Glenfiddich goes down nice,
but it doesn't wipe away
the taste
of that phone call
from those cops.
Topher's still a teenager.
We don't let our boy run wild.
Cal, I was very troubled
when I heard
what happened to your son.
I had no idea there were
minors in my home
or narcotics,
and in no universe
would I approve of that.
All right.
You seem
like a decent man.
Not some 'Frisco nutjob.
I'll submit a detailed report
to the big boss, i.e., my wife,
and, uh, that should
clear things up.
Might not mention
Sandy to her, though.
Nothing like a girl
in a wet suit,
am I right?
You sure are.
Although, I prefer a bikini.
Yeah.
Some of our business
associates in SF,
they're a little funny,
if you catch my drift.
Soft handshakes.
Hell, maybe
we'll get lucky
and all the faggots
will catch that special flu
that's going around.
As long as my son
stays away from it.
But, uh, got plenty of time
to whip him into shape.
Like I said,
he's still a kid.
All right, gentlemen,
it's that time.
All right.
Yes, sir.
Hey, watch it, man.
Do you know,
I wouldn't worry
about your son.
He'll find his path
when he gets away from you.
But I feel sorry
for your wife.
She has to lie there
taking it,
wondering
what the hell she did
to have your stinking
breath in her face.
Or, wait,
maybe I was wrong.
Maybe the big boss
isn't the one taking it.
Hey, Jesus Christ, Joe.
We had the son of a bitch
locked and you had to--
Had to what?
We sell security software
to the government.
Hey, wait.
Come on, hey!
Hey.
It was great hanging out
with you last night.
Mm-hmm.
( keyboard clacking )
- Can I just--
- Uh, yeah.
Sure.
Cool.
I'll let you
get back to work.
( groans )
I heard you two had
a good conversation
last night.
Uh, yeah.
I decided to, uh, keep
the SwapMeet code as it is
and translate
some of Mutiny into C++
to bridge the interface.
Really?
That's great.
The guys are
gonna be thrilled.
And I think
we should fire them.
What? Why?
Do you have an actual,
you know, reason we
can give Diane,
since she's the one
who's gonna have
to pay for it?
Yes.
We don't need them.
Well, the dinner
is tonight.
If you really want
to fire the guys,
then you can
tell Diane yourself.
"You Make Me Wanna Dance"
playing in background
Oh, no!
They have three-player
"Yeti Mountain Mission"?
Race!
No, no, no, no, no.
No video games.
We're here to coalesce
as a group.
- What?
- So line up by "heighth."
- "Heighth"?
Height.
Line up by height.
How tall you are.
- ( laughing )
- Height.
So you're gonna
be at the end.
You're at this end
over here.
- Hey, does hair count?
- Yes, hair counts.
Down here at the end.
Arki, you're in the center.
Lev, you're there.
Wonderboy,
down at the end.
Come on, guys.
Bodie:
Yeah, Wonderboy.
All right, you've been
ordered by Allied Command
to select
12 general prisoners...
- I'm innocent.
- ...convicted by
courts-martial
and sentenced to be executed
or serve lengthy prison terms
for murder, robbery,
striking
a general in the ear,
and other crimes
of violence.
And you will deliver them
behind enemy lines
in France to undertake
a mission of sabotage
that could change
the course of the war.
Okay, Lee Marvin,
but don't most of the guys
in that movie eat it?
By the end, is it more
like the "Dirty Deuce"?
I'll show you
a Dirty Deuce, Bodie.
It's a metaphor.
Actually, it's more
of an allegory.
Uh, pipe down,
Smurfette.
An allegory
is a metaphor.
F you, semen.
Semen?
Did she just
call me semen?
- Man on P.A.: It's time
for the next battle!
- ( feedback squeals )
God.
Players, follow me
for instruction in the rules
of honorable play.
Bodie:
You need to turn
down your toys.
Come on, guys.
Let's see a little bit
of that Apache know-how.
( growls )
( guns blasting )
- Cover me, cover me!
- ( coders shouting )
There he is,
there he is!
- Buckle up, big man.
- Shit!
( shouting indistinctly )
Guys, don't
just stand around.
Fight back!
I'm out, I'm done.
Screw you, asshole.
All right, guys,
green team, gather around,
gather around.
All right,
look, focus, okay?
Guard the base.
Get each other's backs,
all right?
Is this thing even on?
Bodie, get down.
You're in the line of fire!
Wonderboy, get that
out of your mouth.
Come on, man,
get your head in the game.
( blasting )
Hey, guys, check it out.
If you just cover this thing,
you can't get hit.
There must be
a way to disengage
the entire system.
What a bunch of pussies.
That's sexist.
- ( beeps )
- All: Oh!
- He's on our team!
- F off, you big D.
- ( beeps )
- Oh, my God, stop!
We're all gonna die!
It's Judgment Day,
sinners!
- ( shouting )
- Coder: Dodged a shot.
"Goodnight, Saigon"
playing
( all screaming )
Let's do this!
♪ We said we'd all
go down together ♪
♪ Yes, we would all
♪ We said we'd all
go down together ♪
♪ Yes, we would
all go down... ♪
( all yelling )
( all cheering )
Yeah!
( cheering continues )
Sir! Sir!
You are officially
disqualified.
Coders: What?!
( all chanting )
Green! Green! Green!
( echoes )
♪ And who was right? ♪
( chatter )
Craig:
We feel 100% confident.
Doug:
If we're properly assigned,
we can get this whole thing
out the door in three weeks.
Three weeks?
That's much sooner
than we expected, right?
Oh, I just wish--
Let it go.
She's not coming.
( sighs )
I thought you two
had a good conversation.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
We have so much
respect for Cam
and what you guys
have built together.
It sounds nice and all,
but the real question is
can you work with her?
- Definitely.
- Of course.
We just get the feeling
she can't work with us.
You know?
Are we ready
to go ahead and order?
"Cold Siren"
playing in background
♪ Cold, cold creature ♪
♪ And she keeps
her so-called heart ♪
♪ She's a cold, cold,
cold, cold, siren song ♪
♪ A cold,
siren song... ♪
( chatter )
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
Can we have
the check, please?
I just think
if Cam doesn't want
to work with the guys,
she should have
the courage to deal
with it face-to-face.
No, I know.
Look, I wanted her
to tell you,
but since
she's not here...
Cam wants to fire
Doug and Craig.
Really?
That's big.
Yeah.
Do you agree with her?
Well, I--
she's my partner.
Personally, I think
these guys are a big asset.
But your relationship
with Cameron
is the most
important thing.
That's what
I'm investing in.
If working with
Doug and Craig is untenable,
Mutiny can pay
their earn-out early
and send 'em home.
But you just said
that they're a big asset.
I wouldn't
be happy about it,
but it's better than
forcing something toxic.
I just hope it's the guys
who are the problem.
So, how's
the team-building coming?
Well, surprisingly
productive.
Although I've been banned
from future competition
due to my controversial
military tactics.
- ( chuckles )
- You can get out there.
They're still there.
It's stupid fun.
No, I just
came by 'cause I--
well, 'cause
I said I would.
Well, look at you,
Mr. Nice Guy.
Mr. Nice Guy?
Back at Cardiff,
you were the heavy
SVP of Sales.
All those
multimillion-dollar
accounts,
everybody was
scared shitless of you.
You know,
including myself.
But now...
Now what?
Look, I just mean, you know,
being the boss sounds good,
but this is better.
There's minimal
responsibility,
maximum fun.
Which reminds me,
what's that story
you keep telling the guys?
- Something about...
- That thing's outta gas.
( coders laughing )
Bos!
- You should've seen it.
- Oh, man, you're not
gonna believe it.
Gordon went
full-on kamikaze.
He practically
murdered the guy.
It seemed totally
lame at first, but it was
actually pretty awesome.
Yeah, even she
liked it.
( all laugh )
You should play
the next round, man.
- You would shred
this course.
- No.
Coders:
Come on. Come on.
( chanting )
Bos! Bos! Bos!
No, I'm good.
I said I'm good!
Go have another round.
Get on in there.
You guys enjoy it.
- Okay, yeah.
- ( overlapping chatter )
( all cheering )
( guns blasting )
( sighs )
Cam.
What time is it?
It's late.
You missed the dinner.
Oh, my God, Donna,
I'm sorry.
Jesus, I--
I don't know...
I meant to be there.
I planned to be there.
I don't know
what happened.
You're overworked,
that's what happened.
You're exhausted.
Um, how was the dinner?
Fine.
Doug sucked up a lot.
God, I hate that guy.
I know.
But Craig's okay.
Yeah.
After they left,
I told Diane
you want to fire them.
And?
She said no.
What do you mean,
she said no?
They're a part of the deal.
They're an important asset
and we have to find a way
to make it work.
( chuckles )
What?
I thought she
was on our side.
She feels
it's what's best
for the company.
Okay.
( exhales )
Okay, well,
thank you for asking.
I really appreciate it.
Yeah.
- I'll see you at home.
- Yeah.
( door opens, closes )
( door opens )
Hello?
I'm cool to work at night,
but your call kind of
freaked me out.
We lost
General Atomics today.
They represent 37%
of our annual billing.
What happened?
I traded them
for something
more valuable.
What's this?
The log-in credentials
for the ARPANET,
the Department of Defense
packet-switching network.
I secured the information
through General Atomics.
I want you to look into it
before they flag
that my credentials
still work.
Okay, but, you know,
the ARPANET isn't new tech.
It's sort of rusty.
It's not like missile codes
or fighter plane blueprints.
This is--
this is mundane stuff.
I do know that.
It's antiquated.
And that means
it's ripe for an upgrade.
So what should I do?
I need you to go
into it, map it,
and help me figure out
what's next.
- ( duck quacking )
- ( gunshots )
- Cameron: Why?
- ( game chimes )
( Cameron and Gordon
chatting indistinctly )
- Play after this.
- There's two controllers,
though.
Play after I finish
the best out of 10.
Man, you're like some kind
of "Duck Hunt" savant.
Does that mean I'm totally
deficient in other areas?
Like "Duck Hunt" savant,
but bad team player.
Come on.
( groans )
So how's it going with...
( German accent )
...Dick und Doof?
Dick und Doof?
That's what my grandfather
called Laurel and Hardy.
Loosely translates
to "chubby and dumb."
Well, that's perfect,
'cause Doug's the Dick...
Und Craig ist Doof.
- Ja.
( both laugh )
Ahh!
Oh, whatever, though.
I guess I'm gonna
have to make it work.
All right, hope you
haven't lost your edge
now that you're
a peacemaker.
Uh, oh, do you
want a soda?
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah?
- Hey.
- Jesus!
What are you doing?
You know, I wanted
to tell you something.
I've been thinking,
and you should stay here
as long as you want.
You can take your time
finding a place.
( "Duck Hunt" continues
in background )
Oh, thanks.
Yes!
All right,
all you.
Can I ask you a question?
When did you know
you were losing Cardiff?
( gunshot echoes )
( music playing )