[ "London Boys" playing
in background ]
- "Dodge 'Em."
- "Missile Command."
- "Dig Dug."
- "Grand Prix," suckers.
- Carl: Ah!
- Oh!
Gordon, X to you.
Atari 2600 games.
Has to start with
the last letter of
the previous answer.
Uh, "Xenophobe."
Whoa!
Wait, wait, there's seriously
a game called "Xenophobe"?
Yeah, but you're just being
intolerant to aliens,
so it's cool.
All right, guys,
any updates on the bug
we've been having with
the swap confirmations?
Overhauled
and working great.
That's it, ChernobylBoy
is going to the stocks.
- Happy Fourth of July,
asswipe.
- Yeah.
Some fifth grader reneged
on a swap for a "Close
Encounters" lunch pail.
We're revoking
trading privileges
for repeat offenders.
It's all internal for now,
but we're working on putting
this into here.
Show him the guillotine.
( laughs )
But are you dead
in Mutiny?
I mean, are we cancelling
people's subscriptions?
You just wander around
without a head
and that lets people know
this guy without a head
is a total dick.
Don't swap with
this headless dickwad.
( laughs )
Can we get some
blood spurting out
of the neck hole?
- God, how did we
not think of that?
- Put that in, dude! Yes.
All right, we got to solve
for the Sev 1 cache miss bug
in the out-of-region
swap routine?
Tests today,
ships tomorrow.
- You sure?
- Gordo, relax.
SwapMeet's righteous.
The only thing
that's sideways
is people keep ignoring
the no buying stuff rule.
A lot of people
are trading for DBs.
- DBs?
- Dollar bills.
We could technically
monitor every trade to make
sure it doesn't happen.
I can't help you there.
That's way above my pay grade.
( laughs )
So people are buying
shit for money.
So what?
We knew this would happen.
It's clunky.
Our users want an easy
way to buy things
and they're frustrated
it doesn't exist.
Our users want the Police
to get back together,
but Sting's
not interested.
Doug and Craig said
they can spend the weekend
integrating their code
for credit card transactions.
- No.
- They were already in beta with
it when we acquired them.
It's basically
ready to go.
Because they yanked it
off the shelf.
It's boilerplate code
supplied by the credit
card company.
They just gave it
a little shine job.
We don't need
the perfect solution.
If we have to temp
something in now
and customize it
later, fine.
A Band-Aid is better
than bleeding to death.
Bleeding to death?
Donna, SwapMeet
has doubled in size
every week since
we went live.
You're just scared
of slowing down.
I don't want
to slow our growth.
And you keep acting like
accepting credit cards
is some devil's bargain.
They make
people's lives easier.
That's the whole point.
Okay, Mutiny is a castle.
You and I built it
and then we gave a little
piece to Diane.
And then a little piece
to freakin' Doug and Craig.
But making deals with
credit card companies is
just lowering the drawbridge.
What good is a castle
if nobody's in the kingdom?
It doubles in size
every week, okay?
There is a fix for this,
I promise.
I just-- I don't know
what it is yet.
- Hey, Cam,
are you down there?
- Yeah, Bos.
Cam, I'm gonna pick you up
tomorrow at 6:00 A.M.
sharp, all right?
We got to get
to the terminal
a little bit early.
They always give me shit
about the rods in my tailbone.
Okay.
When we moved
here, we knew
that there'd be times
that we'd have
to adapt quickly.
This is one of those times.
Donna, we're all
alone, okay?
There's no other company
that's even attempting
to do what SwapMeet
is doing.
I don't want to rush in
and just screw it up
all at once.
Can we talk about it
when I get back Monday?
- We're not gonna
screw anything--
- Monday.
Have a nice trip.
Stanford's over here
right next to Moffett.
Over here
is jackboot central.
DoD, NORAD, the NSA.
And I printed out all
the directories for every
mainframe on the network.
And we can leverage
some of the weak access
points I found.
Now, the Pentagon
is nearly impenetrable,
but some
of these other guys--
Utah is a total sieve.
What is this right here?
That's not really
part of ARPANET.
That's just the new network
the National Science Foundation
just rolled out.
Yeah, NSFNET.
Steve Wolff's baby.
I went in through
Cornell's node.
It's only been live
for a couple days.
Could you--
could you not do that?
NSFNET's
transmission lines
are 10 times faster
than ARPANET theoretically.
- Uh-huh.
- But it keeps crashing.
- I've been bumped off six
times in less than an hour.
- What else?
Seriously, Joe,
it's just a bunch
of tenure-track slapdicks.
They can't even get their
basic infrastructure right.
They got grants
for the national network,
threw a bunch of cash
at the local level,
and left the regional networks
in the middle hanging.
- So?
- So there's a huge
bottleneck baked in.
There's no room
for increased demand.
- So like ARPANET--
- Commercial use is banned.
There could be
something here.
It's a lemon.
I've been working on it
for six weeks, I know.
Well, you know.
You've been working
on it for six weeks.
General Atomics left
a hole in our balance
sheet $3 million deep.
We're hemorrhaging money.
ARPANET will be
mothballed soon.
And NSFNET is the future.
That's the story
you just told me.
No, Joe.
Listen--
Just dig deeper
on this.
Indulge me.
- That's all for today.
- ( knock on door )
Get some sleep, Ryan.
You're starting
to miss things.
- What are you doing here?
- I need to talk to you.
- It's not a good time.
- Now.
Thank you for today.
( theme music playing )
"Green Ideas" playing
Bosworth:
I'm just so excited
to see this little monkey,
I whizzed right past
Sonny Bryan's.
Hey, when do babies
start talking?
Um, three or four months?
His first words are gonna be
barbecue if I got anything
to say about it.
Oh, hey, check this out.
Remember that stewardess,
the one with the legs?
She gave me that for Sam.
Every time I'd go on a trip
when James was young,
I'd get one of these,
pin it to his teddy bear
first thing in the morning
so he'd know I was home.
That's really sweet, Bos.
So what's the plan?
You gonna ship the bike
or are you gonna ride off
into the sunset,
catch bugs in your teeth
on the way back to the Bay?
You know, I don't even
know if it runs.
I'm kind of playing
this all by ear.
Well, they know
you're back, don't they?
No.
I'm not gonna give
my mom time to work up
some stupid speech.
You'll be glad
you did this.
You're doing
all right, Cam.
I am so sorry.
I thought Linda
would never leave.
She was supposed
to pick up the kids
first thing in the morning.
For her,
this is first thing.
She was telling me about
this creepy dad at school
that keeps asking her
to go boogie boarding
in Capitola.
I think she wants me
to be jealous.
Oh, I am not
drinking out of that.
Hey, look at this.
Remember that bar
we went to
in Independence on our way
to Onion Valley?
The bartender got us
so drunk, we had to sleep
in the car.
Oh, yeah.
( laughs )
Hey, where are
the propane canisters?
I forgot.
But we can go
stop by Orchard Supply
on the way out.
Orchard Supply is not
open on the Fourth.
You know, and this stupid
thing is useless.
Hey, I don't mind sleeping
out under the stars.
Yeah, that's what
the rattlesnakes
want you to do.
( sighs )
You know, what's the point
of even going?
You know,
nothing's working.
Well, the kids are gone
and we haven't
had one night alone
since we got to California.
We could always, you know,
have a vacation at home.
You know what?
We're staying here.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna defrost
the porterhouses.
You can pull out
that lacy thing
with the straps
that I got you
for Easter.
I am changing
into sweatpants.
Or sweatpants.
Look at this.
We got the same hair.
You see?
- You want to hold him?
- Cameron: No, no, no, Bos.
- No, my taxi's coming.
- Hold the baby.
Hold the baby,
Cameron.
Yeah.
Lisa:
Are you sure we can't convince
you to stay, Cameron?
I see the crib got
here in one piece.
Uh, yeah, in a lot
of pieces, actually.
Gonna put it together
this weekend.
Lisa:
Sam's graduating out
of his bassinet.
Bosworth: Already?
Precocious little fella.
Look at him.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Do you remember
when I used to get
these for you?
- Yeah, sure do.
- ( car horn honks )
Oh, that's me.
Okay.
Bosworth:
All right, see you
first thing bright and early.
Congratulations.
Your baby's really cool.
I got to get going, too.
I can't believe
they're making you
work on the Fourth.
Yeah, well,
mouths to feed.
Work's work.
Oh, I know
that kind of work.
- I'll be back soon.
Just got to kiss the ring.
- All right.
Do you want
to talk to Grampy?
Come talk to Grampy.
( sighs )
It's, uh--
it's the Fourth of July.
Right.
I mean, you didn't say
I had the day off, so...
Ryan, it's
the Fourth of July.
So, do you want
me to leave?
No.
No, come on in.
Coffee?
Sure.
Kill the computer.
( computer beeps )
You take it black,
right?
Cream, lots of sugar,
actually.
- ( truck horn blows )
- ( tone beeps )
Oh, hi, it's me.
I'm here in Dallas.
Um...
yeah, I'm staying
at the Motel 6 on...
I actually
don't know where.
There's a Midas
and a Whataburger.
But, uh, okay.
I'm here.
"Nowhere Girl"
playing in background
All right, steaks
will be ready in a few.
Mmm.
( sighs )
God.
Unreal.
Do you hear that?
No.
Exactly.
No modems screeching
like a dying hamster.
God, she can be
so stubborn.
And, you know, you wouldn't
think somebody so punk
would be so conservative
when it comes to business.
Yeah, I was really just
talking about the modem.
But, sure, I get it.
It's stressful.
But Cameron's been great
for the most part.
You know,
the kids love her.
Of course, I guess
that's a mixed bag.
I mean, she makes
you better, right?
You know what?
I really don't want
to talk about work.
I wasn't talking
about work.
Oh, well, I really
don't want to talk
about Cameron.
Oh.
Well, what do you want
to talk about?
I don't really want
to talk at all.
"Crazy Jenny"
playing in background
( laughs )
And then we acquired
this company, which was insane
because our payroll
doubled, like, overnight.
Which is fine because
that's what people say
you have to do
to be competitive
in Silicon Valley,
so that's what we did.
Uh, but, yeah, so the thing
that we acquired,
it's called SwapMeet
and it started off--
I know about SwapMeet.
It's pretty hard to miss
'cause I'm still a subscriber.
- Yeah.
I actually almost pulled
the trigger on a swap
for this
"Centipede" cabinet,
but the shipping
from Winnipeg
was ridiculous.
Can I refill
for y'all?
I'm-- I'm okay,
but if you...
Just the check.
Hey, I'm really sorry
that I didn't reach out.
I wanted to write,
but I'm--
I'm not very good
with words
unless it's, like,
part of a chunk of code.
And honestly, I wasn't sure
if you wanted to hear from me.
- It was good
to get your call.
- Yeah.
I mean, I didn't come
just to see you.
I came to grab
some stuff from my mom.
Well, you're gonna see her.
That's-- that's great, right?
Yeah, I mean,
she and Len are moving,
so just got to get
what I came here for
and then get
the hell out.
I don't know,
she just--
if I had my way,
I wouldn't have to
see her at all, but...
I'm really happy
to see you.
Don't.
Come on.
I mean, you--
here, why don't
you get this
and start working off
that plane ticket that
you never used.
I'm kidding.
It's just a joke.
I'll get it.
It's like a $3
business expense.
I can write it off.
It's fine.
Yeah, okay.
Thanks.
They quit for the holiday
before they finished
the new one.
But what do you think?
What's replacing me?
Ryan:
Denture cream.
The lottery.
This city.
I can't decide
if it's beautiful
or horrifying.
My mom came out here.
She died here.
Nothing lasts
in this place.
The whole city
burned down seven times
in the first couple years
of its existence.
Even its name
has been reinvented.
You know what San Francisco
used to be called?
Yeah, Yerba Buena.
Look, that's what makes
this city so great.
You can screw up,
you can fail,
and so what?
You get another chance.
- It's disposable.
- It's exciting.
'Cause you never know
what the hell's next.
Denture cream.
( chuckles )
I'm not sure I've got
another next in me.
You should know that.
"Train in Vain" playing
You say you stand
by your man
Tell me something
I don't understand...
Oh, my God.
I haven't heard
this song in years.
Was that totally
hot sex worth burning
the steaks or what?
Oh, God,
a billion times yes.
To the best
vacation ever.
Did you stand by me
No, not at all...
- ( laughs )
-  Did you stand by me
No way
All the times
When we were close
I'll remember
These things the most
I see all my dreams
come tumbling down
I can't be happy
Without you around...
I love you.
I love you, too.
There's only one
thing I can say
You didn't stand by me
No, not at all,
did you stand by me...
True fact-- a banana peel
will shine your shoes
like no other.
Saved me a mint
in my 20s.
Yeah, I think I've read
that somewhere.
Oh, you did, huh?
Oh, there he is.
Hey.
( car door closes )
- Hey.
- Hey, hi.
I got a little--
got ribs
and hoecake for you.
Um, yeah.
And, oh, there's some--
you know, there's some
fireworks going on out there
that are pretty incredible.
Shh, shh.
Lisa:
He's in the nursery.
Your dad built the crib.
He's been a huge help.
Even went out
for some diapers.
No, no, no.
I was gonna build
that crib.
Sam will be up
in a couple hours.
I'm going to bed.
Well, I think
we could all use
some sleep.
Yeah. Yeah, okay,
Mr. Family Man.
Nobody's blaming you
for being gone, James.
Well, maybe I should
have brought home some
pilot wings, huh?
Maybe that would
make up for it.
You loved those
when you were a kid.
Hell, you had
a whole box of them.
Yeah, I had a whole box
of them because Mom
was a stewardess.
I just tossed the ones
you gave me on top.
You can rewrite
history to impress
your 15-year-old boss,
but you don't fool me.
Hey, what's that place
we used to go eat at
down in the South Bay?
Oh, Los Gatos Cafe.
- Yeah.
- Those eggs Benedict.
I'm taking you there
tomorrow for brunch.
One last hurrah before
the crazies return.
Well, we definitely
worked up an appetite.
God, twice in one day.
We should do that
more often.
Twice in one week
is above average.
We have not had sex
twice in one day
since Gerald Ford
was in the office.
- No, that's not true.
- It's totally true.
Pre-kid.
Do the math.
Carry the one.
Ford.
Oh, my God.
We really needed this.
I'm so glad
we didn't go camping.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I'm so glad
to hear you say that.
Yeah?
I mean,
we're not as young
as we used to be.
Yeah.
But, you know,
even then
popping a squat
behind a tree
and your back kills
when you wake up.
No, thank you.
Yeah, but...
you loved
all those times
at Mt. Tam.
Eh.
What?
Yosemite was
freaking awesome.
You know what it is?
It's like that saying
about what crazy is.
That you do the same thing
a ton of times
and you're like,
"This always sucks."
That's insanity.
It's doing the same thing
over and over and expecting
a different result.
Yeah. Yes.
Camping is insanity.
( laughs )
Oh, God.
I am exhausted.
( yawns )
( whistling )
- ( exploding )
- ( cheering )
( distant fireworks
exploding )
( sloshing )
( fireworks whistling,
exploding )
( car horns honking )
( Joe sobbing )
Bosworth: Hell, if you're not
gonna eat the rest of the
thing, then I want it.
You know how hard it is to get
a halfway decent breakfast
burrito in the Bay Area?
It's a fool's errand.
Thank you.
It's funny.
It's not where I pictured
you growing up.
I didn't.
No?
Oh, that hombre's back.
He brought cash with him.
You gonna do
what you came here
for or what?
Shh, don't.
Cameron, I know
the first 2,000 miles
are easy
and the last 20 feet
are hard,
but you've come all this way
and now here we are.
Okay.
You owe this
to yourself.
And to them.
Come--
he's buying
your dad's bike,
Cameron.
Fine. Just stop
talking, okay?
That's yours.
Go get it.
Stop it!
What the hell
are you doing?
People don't make
mistakes because they
don't love you, Cameron.
They make mistakes
because they do.
Oh, that is such
a crock of shit
even from you.
You want me to pick up
the slack for you again?
Great, why should today
be any different, huh?
Would you stop?
Cameron, you didn't
come here just for the bike.
- Come on, now.
- Jesus Christ!
Listen, you might
think you're my father,
but you're not, okay?
I know that,
God damn it.
No, no, I don't
think you do.
( motor running )
( engine starts )
( tires squeal )
Oh, wow.
Oh, hey.
Thought I'd get
a jump-start on the day.
Great.
So Los Gatos Cafe?
I'm really jonesing
for that eggs Benedict.
Yeah.
I don't know.
The kids will
be home soon.
Rain check?
Everything all right?
Yeah.
Everything's fantastic.
I'm gonna go
work on the ham
if it's all the same.
Oh.
You know, get some
good ham time in.
- Oh, sure.
- Yeah.
There's some leftover
pizza in the fridge
if you want some.
( knocks )
( phone rings )
Any word from
the boss man?
She even coming in?
It's already noon.
We're ready
to move ahead.
Just say the word.
I have to talk
to her first.
There's a petition up
right now on Community.
It's called 1986 BC.
It demands we let users
pay with actual money.
Hundreds of people
have already signed.
- It was posted
two hours ago.
- Okay, guys.
One user just emailed me
thanking Mutiny
for reviving
the "efficiency
and modernity of
the barter system."
- Doug:
He signed it Methuselah.
- ( door closes )
Donna:
Just wait, okay?
My answer is the same
as it was an hour ago.
Take a knee
or whatever.
( knocks )
How was Texas?
Still big.
How was camp?
- Didn't go.
- Peaches.
Was the plane delayed?
Got into San Jo'
8:00 A.M. right on time.
I just needed a morning,
so I took it.
Okay.
Look, I don't know
where she is, Donna.
She didn't even get
on the damn plane.
You left her
in Texas?
I'm not
her keeper, Donna.
And you have no idea
where she is?
Kid was at a Motel 6
on I-30.
Beyond that, like I said,
it's one big-ass state.
( sighs )
( "Walking Out on Love"
playing in background )
"Night Princess."
"Spy Hunter."
- "Root Beer Tapper."
- What?
Gordo,
ColecoVision games.
Hey, stupid Gordon,
your stupid turn.
R to you.
- Pass.
- ( imitates buzzer )
Gordo's in a mood.
Hey, Donna.
The guy at the Motel 6
said she checked out.
How long will it take?
We can start beta tests
internally today.
Be live in under a week.
Okay, then do it.
And Cameron's okay
with that?
Cameron's not here.
She'll catch up.
Ryan: Joe, check this out.
Something weird going on
near Ithaca.
Found some code fragments
with the same fingerprint
as IBM, Kodak, Xerox.
Hey, Joe?
Yeah.
You okay?
Okay, I don't know exactly
what we're looking at here,
but the slapdicks
have given way to
the big swinging variety
and they're working
on something together
called NYSERNET.
That's interesting.
Interesting, yeah,
but it doesn't do much
to fill the money hole
you're so worried about.
God, you're doing
great work here.
( phone rings )
Hello?
- Woman: May I speak
with Joe MacMillan?
- This is he.
Mr. MacMillan,
I'm calling from
the San Francisco City Clinic.
Is this a good time
to discuss your recent visit?
Hold on one second.
We're done for the day.
I'm ready.
Mr. MacMillan,
I have the results
of your HIV antibody test.
Since you were
in contact...
( "New Misery" playing )
( beeps )
( "Ammunition" playing
in background )
- ( phone rings )
- Hello.
New user sign-ups
saw a welcome spike
after we integrated
SwapMeet,
but we're fielding
too many complaints
about the lack
of support for our
monetary transactions.
So tonight we will go live
with the credit card code
that Doug and Craig
have been testing all week.
Man:
Look who it is.
It's Cameron.
Cameron's back.
Donna:
When users purchase
something,
we charge them
for the item and we add
a small transaction fee.
Mail checks to sellers
for the sales price--
What's this?
Well, first of all,
welcome back.
I think I speak
for all of us when I say
I'm glad you're okay.
I've been working.
We've all been working.
Cameron:
I can see that.
I have a solve
for transactions.
We've been in beta
on a credit card interface
all week.
Doug and Craig's code?
Yeah, it works great.
Okay, so you just went ahead
and did that without me.
Could you all excuse us?
Cameron and I need
the room, please.
Hey, so let me see
if I've got this.
So let's say
I want to buy a,
I don't know,
first Superman comic
for $100.
Mutiny charges my AmEx,
adds five bucks.
As a transaction fee.
But AmEx takes
three of those dollars
as their transaction fee,
so Mutiny is only making
two bucks.
Meanwhile, I'm really
pissed because yesterday
I could have shelled out
100 DBs for that Superman
and today I'm shelling
out an extra five bucks
for nothing.
It's not nothing.
We're providing
a valuable service.
Oh, spoken like
a true middleman.
Okay, so what's
your solution?
Routing numbers.
It's how banks
move money.
And our subscribers pay
by checks, so their account
numbers are already on file.
Okay, you sell me Superman.
Mutiny pulls funds
directly from my bank
and deposits them
into your account
using our own
ABA routing number
as a pipeline.
Oh, and it's basically free
because we don't incur
a transaction fee
and we don't charge one
either because our expenses
haven't skyrocketed.
But then with your way,
we'd need, what,
three people handling
credit card transactions,
a few people to handle
check writing and mailing,
probably an accountant
or two.
So that's, what,
12 new hires?
Yeah, that's about right.
Okay, my way adds
one person.
One.
I can't believe you.
Right back at you.
We agreed to discuss this
when I got back.
We agreed to discuss
this on Monday.
It's Friday.
Where have you been?
Who cares?
I'm here now.
Since when do you make
decisions for my company
without consulting me?
God damn it,
I tried to consult you
and I couldn't find you.
Oh, my God,
this is exactly what
I've been worried about.
- What?
- Every new person that walks
through that door,
another piece of Mutiny
gets cut away from me.
No, no, no, Donna.
Mutiny isn't just my job,
it's who I am.
It's who I am, too.
I couldn't sleep all week.
I could ignore the mountain
of complaints in my in-box,
but I care too much.
I came up with
a better solution.
Just because you think
you need to sprinkle
your fairy dust
over everything around here
before you feel satisfied
doesn't mean it's better.
No, it is better.
Oh, God.
Okay, but that's
not the point.
We were in real trouble.
And when I'm in trouble
and I look around,
I need to find you there.
We need to have
each other's backs.
Sometimes I need
to crawl into a hole
just find my head.
I know you're patient with me
even when I drag my feet.
I know I should find
my own place to live
and stop imposing
on you guys.
And I know that--
that dinner with Doug
and Craig that I missed
that you probably didn't
think we should fire them,
but you went to bat for me
anyways with Diane.
I know that.
I was with Tom, okay?
That's where I was.
Yeah, I was wondering.
Still, you should
have called.
He said that you're
the best thing that
ever happened to me.
And it's true.
And not 'cause he said it
or anything, just--
you anchor me.
So I guess
we're like a bank now.
That's pretty
cool, huh?
( chuckles )
It's a routing number.
We're not giving away
free toasters or anything.
I do have
your back, Donna.
I have a weird way
of showing it,
but I swear I do.
I have yours.
This and only this
is what we focus on.
Okay, yeah, time-out.
This is super cool to me,
but only NSFNET?
The yarn you just pulled,
those are the deep pockets.
Exactly.
It's virgin territory.
Wolff created
a bottleneck, right?
Yeah, no support
for regional networks.
The guy is insane.
The guy is brilliant.
He's sending a signal.
He's like our Gorbachev.
Do you know
what Glasnost is?
I want to say either
a vodka or a satellite.
Wolff knows
that the only way
his network will grow
is if private money
gets in the game.
The problem is
that's against the law
for now.
- But...
- But maybe one day
it won't be.
And when the rules change,
people are going to flood in.
Average people at home
on their Apple IIe and Amiga
and it's gonna overload
the system.
So who breaks
the bottleneck?
We are going to create
a regional network
right there.
The past--
the past is a bunch
of fortresses
all closed off
from the rest
of the world.
We don't have to build
a faster computer
or dream up the next
killer application.
That's what you do
in a fortress.
We are going to pave
a road between them.
And you're going
to ask the board to go
deeper in the hole
on something that may
never turn a dime?
I don't care what
the board thinks anymore.
Money is just
a side effect.
Glasnost.
It means openness.
And it's always a bad idea
to bet against openness.
- Are you hungry?
- I don't know, Joe.
You don't know
if you're hungry?
I don't even know
what to think anymore.
I try to decipher
your sayings,
but then the phone
rings and you boot me
to another zip code.
And we still
haven't figured out
how to make any money
and I go home every day
and I'm spinning
and I don't even know
if you like me.
I feel crazy.
You're not going
crazy, Ryan.
You're hungry.
Look, I've had
a tough week.
Will you join me
for dinner?
Okay.
Okay, I'll come
to dinner with you.
Sounds nice.
Just take a good look.
That's what's next.
( phone rings )
Diane Gould.
Diane, hi.
It's Cameron Howe.
Cameron.
What's going on?
I had a talk with Donna
earlier today
and I wanted to call
and say I know I've been
a little eccentric lately.
Someone once told me
that eccentric
is just a fancy word
for asshole.
I'm a little eccentric
myself.
And you have to be
if you want to make it
as a woman in this business.
This routing number thing
is really great.
Yeah, okay, I also
just wanted to call
and say thanks for,
you know,
seeing that Mutiny Exchange
wasn't something we could do
on our own
and that it was smart
to buy SwapMeet.
And, yes, I don't love
Doug and Craig,
but I really totally respect
your decision to keep them
at the company.
Like I told Donna,
I'd have paid
for them to go away.
Cost of doing business.
But it shows strength
that you decided
to make it work.
Look,
this call is appreciated,
but it's unnecessary.
It's your company.
You don't have to apologize
for any decision.
In the end,
you decide.
Cameron?
Uh, yeah.
Okay, thanks, Diane.
I've got to go.
Bye.
( door opens )
( indistinct chatter )
( breathing heavily )
Donna:
I'm gonna go check
on the kids real quick.
( music playing )