Joe:
So when does that 3090
get delivered?
They said by
5:00 P.M. today.
And we've got Stanford
on Monday, right?
Cisco and MCI
the week after.
I'd take a good look.
Soon it'll be hardware
and handshake deals,
endless troubleshooting
and upgrades.
But right now--
right now it's perfect.
The room?
The idea.
All goes well,
by the end of the month
we'll be sitting down
with the sector chief
of NSFNET
to walk him through
the bid.
It's Mitch Klowden.
We go back
to my IBM days.
He's a good guy.
Sharp dresser.
"Jockey Full of Bourbon"
playing
♪ Edna Million
in a drop-dead suit ♪
♪ Dutch pink
on a downtown train ♪
♪ $2 pistol, but the gun
won't shoot ♪
♪ I'm in the corner
on the pouring rain ♪
♪ 16 men on
a dead man's chest ♪
♪ And I've been drinking
from a broken cup ♪
♪ Two pairs of pants
and a mohair vest ♪
♪ I'm full of bourbon,
I can't stand up ♪
♪ Hey, little bird,
fly away home ♪
♪ Your house is on fire,
your children are alone♪
♪ Hey, little bird,
fly away home ♪
♪ Your house is on fire,
your children are alone ♪
♪ Hey, little bird,
fly away home ♪
♪ Your house is on fire,
your children are alone ♪
♪ Hey, little bird,
fly away home ♪
♪ Your house is on fire,
your children are alone ♪
♪ Hey. ♪
Well, this all sounds
fantastic.
I have to discuss it
with the team,
but I should have an answer
for you by Monday.
- Excellent.
- And you.
Where'd you find
this one, hmm?
Great to meet you, Ryan.
Hell of a head on
those shoulders.
Thank you, Mitch.
And a nice cut
on that suit.
Mitch, it was great
to see you again.
- Great to see you, Joe.
- Thank you for coming by.
( sighs )
"1982-No Fun"
playing over headset
Did I get the wrong time?
Bosworth:
No, your info's
as good as mine.
Haven't seen Mutt
or Jeff all day.
And the ladies are in
their respective foxholes
as seems to be their wont
these days.
Do you ever try
to be the bigger man
in this business,
but the universe
just gives you a shit
sandwich for your efforts?
Indeed I have.
( laughs )
But I'm treating
myself to "Turan-dot,"
so I can't complain.
- What?
- "Turan-dot."
The opera.
I'm broadening
my horizons.
Know my new town.
It's "Turandot."
- Hmm.
- Hey.
Sorry, guys.
I got stuck on a call.
Okay, let's get started.
Uh, shouldn't we wait
for Doug and Craig?
That would be
a waste of time.
- Why?
- I fired them.
When?
This morning.
Why?
Well, SwapMeet's
fully integrated
and the cash
feature's bug-free,
so I no longer need them.
And what are we going to do
about their earn-out?
I feel like Diane
was pretty clear she wanted us
to make it work.
Was she?
Yeah, I mean...
why would you--
I just wish
you'd discussed it
with us first.
- ( knocks )
- ( door opens )
Sorry, Diane Gould is here
for both of you.
Oh, should be fun.
( theme music playing )
Well, I must admit
I'm surprised.
I thought you all had found
a manageable workflow.
Well, we discussed it
and we decided
that Doug and Craig's
usefulness had run
its course.
And we both figured based
on our earlier conversations
that you'd have
our backs on this.
Well, as I've said,
I'll authorize the earn-out
if that's what
you feel you need.
But that's not what
I'm here to discuss.
I have news.
You have
an acquisition offer.
From CompuServe.
Uh... ( chuckles )
CompuServe?
I know. I don't think
it's a good fit either,
but it sets a floor.
How much?
20 million.
That's four times
what Westgroup offered.
I mean, have we really
grown that fast?
Here's the thing,
and I didn't think
we'd be having
this conversation so soon,
but I think it's a good
time to consider
the possibility
of an IPO.
The things we could do
with that influx of cash.
Okay, it's not
like we'd get to spend
the money, though, right?
I mean, we'd have
to get a board and chase
quarterly earnings.
Absolutely, but it's also
important to consider
the landscape.
Look at Sun, Oracle.
I mean, Jesus, the money
that Microsoft has raised.
Plus right now Mutiny
is the dominant player
in the online
transaction market.
Once they hear the news
of this offer,
there'll be imitators.
I mean, just think,
everything we've ever
wanted to play with.
We could hire
a whole team for R&amp;D.
Yeah, okay, I'm not chopping
my company up into pieces
so that you can ring
a bell on Wall Street.
Okay, this is just a lot.
I need time to process it.
Sure, okay.
You think about it.
Take all the time
you need.
This is a huge decision
and both of you should take
a lot of time with it.
But whatever you have
going on here, you need
to deal with it.
I'll tell you what.
I have a place
up in Sonoma.
It's a little vineyard.
It's quite peaceful.
It's a good place
to get your thoughts
in order.
Why don't you guys go there,
take the weekend,
get on the same page?
We'd love to.
Great.
I'll be around all weekend
if you want to talk any
of this through.
Thanks, Diane.
Really.
So do you want to drive up
tonight or tomorrow?
Yeah, uh, well,
while a wine farm
retreat with you sounds
super romantic,
I am busy this weekend.
Modern society sits
on a foundation
of services
we now take for granted.
Railroads.
Highways.
Water.
Power.
Network computing
will be the next great
public utility.
My actions have placed us
at the vanguard
and we are poised
to reap vast rewards.
America's early entrepreneurs
were bound by space and time.
This new network
will be limitless.
Just-- I just--
just to be clear,
ahem, the N-- what?
The NSFNET
is nonprofit, right?
It's just for research labs
and governments and colleges.
- There is no commercial use?
- That's correct.
- On page--
- 22.
--there's a memo from
Taylor and Ernst Strategies.
They anticipate a five-year
legislative process.
Sanderson:
And we've already spent
six million on the 3090
and another 400,000
on routers and switches.
Wait, with these speed
and capacity issues,
why are we investing
in faster equipment than
the network can bear?
It's only 56K now,
but all signs
point to a T1 upgrade
coming soon.
Guys, I understand
the skepticism.
There's no denying
this is a bold futures bet,
but it is a sure one.
It may take some time,
but the money will come.
You know what, gentlemen?
Why don't we do this?
Why don't we take
the weekend
to digest
this impressive proposal?
What do you say?
Yeah?
Good.
Thank you very much.
( clears throat )
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Pleasure.
- Great to see you again.
- Thank you.
Hey, you owe me 18.
Hey, good seeing you.
Say hi to Becky
for me, okay?
( chatter fades )
I love the ambition.
I do.
- I just need
you to slow down.
- We wait, we lose.
I hear you, I do.
And I believe in
your vision.
That's why I'm here,
but please, Joe...
no more purchases.
- No promises.
- Just get them on board.
That's why you're here.
( door closes )
Well, this is
the process, you know?
You should have
seen their faces
when I told them the Citadel
was going to be free.
Good work today.
"Anarchy" playing
in background
( indistinct chatter )
( knocks )
Yeah?
Are you sure
you don't mind
me going?
No, it's fine.
It's fine.
Well, I appreciate it.
I really need some time
away from Cameron.
And I just need one
damn hour of peace, okay?
- The girls think
this place is--
- Oh, my God.
- Donna!
- Babe, I'm so sorry.
- Which one do you want?
- This one.
Thank you.
Who you talking to?
Just some guys.
Well, I'm glad
you're having fun.
( video game beeping,
music playing )
No! Ah!
Sorry.
Now, wait, wait.
Slow down, you're gonna
miss the coin room.
- Where?
- The tube on the left.
- But watch out
for the piranha.
- No! No!
- Can we please play now?
- In a second.
We're better
at the bosses.
Then how come
you're dead?
Look, guys, why don't
y'all go outside, okay?
It's nice out.
Just till we finish
this world.
But that'll be
40 and 100 hours.
Look, you guys go outside,
ride some bikes.
As soon as you get back,
okay, you can have
a turn. I promise.
- Whatever.
- It's Joanie's
Nintendo anyway.
Let's beat
the game today.
Come on, Donna's away.
When else are we
gonna do it?
Let's just see
how far we get before
the girls get back.
( game beeping )
If we could just skip
the water world.
I hate the water world.
"Your princess
is in another castle."
( sighs )
Look, if we don't
beat it this time,
then I think I gotta
call it quits for the day.
Okay?
What are you doing?
- Whoa.
- What are you doing?
- Yes.
- Yes!
- Holy shit!
- Welcome to the warp zone!
Oh, God, I can't believe
it took me this long.
Here, here, here.
You go. You're better
at the cloud level.
- Okay.
- Whoa!
- Oh, it's on now.
It's on now.
- Yes, yes.
- Come here, you spiny,
turtle-birthing butt.
- Oh, my God.
( exhales )
( laughs )
Yes, kill it.
Watch out.
( high-pitched ringing )
Gordon?
Jesus Christ.
- Gordon, are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Gordon?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- What? What the hell
just happened?
- I'm fine.
I just--
I just need
to eat something.
What?
I'm fine.
"Quanto è Bella" playing
♪ Quanto è bella,
quanto è cara ♪
♪ Piu la vedo
e piu mi piace ♪
♪ Ma in quel cor
non son capace ♪
♪ Lieve affetto
ad inspirar ♪
♪ Essa legge,
studia, impara ♪
♪ Non vi ha cosa
ad essa ignota ♪
♪ Lieve affetto
ad inspirar. ♪
( laughs )
"Shake the Hippie"
playing
- Push.
- I am pushing.
Oh.
Whoa.
♪ But I told you
not to worry ♪
♪ Nothing I do
will make you sorry ♪
♪ You do the hippie... ♪
- ( video game
music playing )
- Okay.
I'm not buying it.
The blood sugar excuse.
It's neurological.
I've been dealing with it
for about a year.
They-- they found
very small areas
of atrophy.
So technically
it's degenerative, but--
Jesus Christ.
- So you're dying?
- No.
No, I'm not dying.
I mean, we're all--
we're all dying,
but, no,
it's under control.
I'm taking medication
and most days I'm fine.
Other days--
You pile-drive a Zenith.
( chuckles )
No, that's a--
that was a first.
Donna knows?
Who else?
Where are the router
configurations
for the existing
Fuzzballs?
Uh, they should be in
the binder with the rest
of the UCSD research.
Okay.
- ( phone rings )
- Oh.
Yeah, this is Joe.
Hey, Mitch.
Didn't expect to hear
from you on a Saturday.
Is everything all right?
That's great news.
Great news.
I assure you
the feeling is mutual.
( chuckles )
Mitch, we should
hire you to run PR.
( laughs )
Yeah, me, too.
Uh, hey, listen.
Messenger over
the paperwork on Monday
and I'll have my lawyers
go through it ASAP.
Yeah, we'll be talking.
- Oh!
- ( laughs )
Hey, congrats.
- You made it
on the train.
- Yeah!
Where's that
UCSD binder?
We should celebrate.
Celebrate?
That bid
they just approved
is half fiction.
Now we make it real.
Come on,
let's get to it.
But, Joe,
right now
it's perfect.
Have you ever had
30-year-old scotch?
( laughs )
( door opens )
( clock ticking )
- Hello?
- Oh, my God!
Oh, you're
Diane's daughter.
I recognize you
from the pictures.
I'm Donna Clark.
I work with your mom.
Oh, hi. Sorry.
Yes, I'm Kimberly.
- Kimmie, everything okay?
- Oh, I'm fine. It's fine.
This is Donna.
She works with my mom.
This is my boyfriend Travis.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- And his roommate Rob.
Hello.
Is that
my mom's sweater?
I was just in the bath.
I'm so sorry.
I can go get a hotel.
No, no, no, no. Please.
We just decided to drive up
from Berkeley today.
We can totally drive back.
Oh, no, don't do that.
No, it's fine.
I'm kind of supposed to ask
before I come up here anyway.
Well, look,
it's a huge house.
I brought more food
than I can possibly eat.
So what about this--
I don't tell your mom
I saw you
and we keep it between us
that I was trying on
her clothes?
( laughs )
- ( video game beeping )
- That's insane.
Yeah, I know.
Did you consider it?
Sort of.
I mean, it was 70%
of a fortune.
Well, souls
don't come cheap.
I don't understand
how you're so good
at the underwater level.
It's a gift.
- ( game pauses )
- ( sighs )
You know, I don't even
really care about the money.
I just want him
to admit what he did.
Yeah.
All right,
you can do this.
- Okay.
- I believe in you.
- Wish I could pelt Joe
with fireball--
- Shh.
Don't.
- Yeah! Finally!
- Yeah!
- Victory!
- Finally.
( growls )
( chuckles )
- You want to see
something cool?
- Yeah.
The radio spectrum's like
a long measuring tape.
- Uh-huh.
- The AM band's
the low frequency.
And it's down here
on the bottom.
And the FM is way
up here on the top.
- You follow?
- ( laughs )
Man, Gordon,
I got to be honest.
I didn't know what
you were doing in here,
but this is pretty rad.
You really think so?
I mean, it's kind of silly.
No, no, I mean it.
I think it's cool.
Yeah, well, I wish Donna
shared your enthusiasm.
Yeah.
You know, I hope you
realize what a rare thing
you've done.
- Mm-hmm.
- You and Donna.
I mean, you guys
built something real.
Yeah, so did you.
Oh, please.
You don't have
to do that.
I built a couple
of machines no one
will remember
and a piece of software
everybody thinks is Joe's.
Enough about
that jackass.
Let's fire this thing up.
( switch clicks )
That's weird.
I was just talking
on it last night.
Maybe there's
a loose connection.
Oh, you sure
about that?
Here.
Fire it up.
- ( static hissing )
- Hmm.
- ( button clicks )
- CQ.
( chatting )
Hey there.
Could I just get
two fingers
of something brown
back there?
Did-- did you hear?
Could we just pretend
that you were holding
a place in line for me?
Well, look who it is.
Uh, this young lady
will have a gin and tonic
with lime, please.
( laughs )
- Are you here with someone?
- No, flying solo.
What can I say?
Me and Puccini
go way back.
You?
It's a blind date.
He's a friend of a friend
of a banker or something.
I forget how
I ended up here.
I have enjoyed our time
together, Doris.
Gracias.
Well, thank you
for saving me.
You don't strike me much
like a woman needs saving.
( bell chimes )
Hey, listen.
There's a bar
I pass on the way here.
Looks like a good time.
We can get another
cocktail after the show.
Give me two minutes.
I'll meet you outside.
Here's to me, Doris.
"Struttin'" playing
over headset
( keyboard clicking )
"Ever Green" playing
in background
But, of course,
he is nowhere to be found.
And, of course,
the emergency exit
locks behind me.
So I'm totally naked,
super drunk
with this alarm blaring
and he and my coat
are at a different door,
but I didn't know that.
So I ran all the way
back to my dorm
ducking behind bushes
like some cartoon spy.
Thank God it was finals week
and no one was around.
I hope you
broke up with him.
I married him, actually.
( laughing )
Oh, no.
I can't believe
you actually work at AGG.
Oh, no, no, your mom's
an investor in my company.
It's an online service
called Mutiny.
Shut up.
- You own Mutiny?
- Yeah, a part of it.
Wait, are you CamHowe?
This is insane.
I'm EstimatedProphet.
No, no,
Cam is my partner.
It's like the best.
I'd been looking
for a tape
of this June
'77 Winterland show
for literally years.
Signed up on Mutiny,
found it 20 minutes later.
That's great.
So, Donna,
you and my mom
should be friends.
Oh, I think
we are friends.
No, yeah, I mean,
friend friends.
'Cause all my mom's got
are work friends
and everyone else
was Dad's.
Well, I'm sure it took
a lot of nights and weekends
to build a firm
with her name on the door.
That couldn't
have been easy.
Except the name's
Dad's, too, which sucks.
I just think
you're fun and smart
and she must really like
you 'cause she does not let
a lot of people up here.
Well, I like her, too.
Hey, you guys, do you have
any of that pot left?
( chuckles )
Well, yeah, but...
What?
If you're maybe
looking for a different
sort of adventure.
So I have
a confession.
Shoot.
I don't care much
for Texas.
( laughs )
Why ever not?
Isn't it just a bunch
of good old boys
in Dixie Trans Ams
speeding down dirt roads?
That'd be Georgia.
And the General Lee
is a Charger.
- Okay.
- Never been, I take it.
No, I have not.
Tell me about it.
Well, it's like
any other place
except more so.
Really?
Like this place?
Well, we get all kinds.
Have to admit,
not what I had in mind
when we walked in here,
but glad we did.
So you still have
family there, yeah?
Here.
( laughs )
That little feller.
Oh, my God.
He's beautiful.
Yeah.
( sighs )
It's a hell of a thing,
ain't it?
God, it feels like it was
just a few days ago that
I was braiding Kim's hair.
And now she has one year
left at Berkeley.
Everybody says
it passes so fast.
I don't know.
Working as much as I do,
I missed a lot.
( exhales )
Yeah, you and me both.
I thought I was
gonna retire in Texas.
You know, be around.
I'd take little Sam
to a ball game a couple
times a month.
I wanted to be able
to tell him I did things
that mattered.
Now I got stories
no one cares about.
( scoffs )
Foolish things
coming from a man
my age.
Apologies.
No, not at all.
Man:
Gentlemen, welcome
to the stage
- Lady Divine.
- ( applause )
- Gordon?
- Oh, hey.
- Hi.
- I didn't
wake you, did I?
No, no,
I'm just heading out.
Okay, uh...
well, good night.
- Hey, Cam.
- Yeah?
It was really fun today.
Yeah, it was.
Bye, Gordon.
"Mercy Street" playing
( sighs )
♪ Looking down
on empty streets ♪
♪ All she can see ♪
♪ Are the dreams
all made solid ♪
made real ♪
♪ All of the buildings,
all of the cars were once... ♪
You came.
I figured we should talk.
Come, sit with me.
I don't like this.
I don't like
feeling this way.
I hate it, too.
I don't know
how we got here.
You lied to me, Donna.
I know, but I--
it didn't feel like
a lie at the time.
It felt like what
was best for the company,
like what was best
for you.
I am just as good
at this as you are.
No one ever said
you weren't.
They don't have to say it.
It's there all the time.
It's deafening.
Cam is the genius.
Donna is the mom.
So we're back
where we started.
No.
No, not yet.
I mean,
look at this place.
Did you ever think
we'd be here?
How many times do you need
to hear that I can't
do this without you?
I'm sorry that
I lied to you.
I forgive you.
♪ Mercy, mercy ♪
♪ Looking for mercy ♪
♪ Looking for mercy. ♪
- ( breathing heavily )
- ( zipper zips )
- Well...
- Not the night
I was expecting.
- Nor I.
Why don't you come
back to the house
for a nightcap?
You know, it's getting
a little late.
Let me just--
I'll just drop you
back at your car.
You know, I could--
I could...
come by.
No, it's fine.
( engine starts )
You need to give
Gordon credit.
- ( stammers )
- ( key jingles )
Be pissed at me.
You have every right.
Just, Jesus,
don't take it out
on Gordon.
He needs this.
Joe, do right by him.
Give him credit
for what he built.
Say something.
Shall we celebrate?
Why?
That's a wedding ring
on your finger, isn't it?
( cork pops )
I came here
to talk about Gordon.
Did you?
It's 1:30 in the morning.
You were waiting
in my hallway.
To talk about Gordon?
Is it what's his name?
It doesn't matter.
Could have been anyone.
You were happy for a moment
and you thought the person
standing closest to you
was the source.
Trust me.
I've been there.
( glass thuds )
You need to give
Gordon credit.
( door opens, closes )
- ( game beeping )
- Donna: Hello.
Hello, I'm home.
- Mommy, Mommy!
- Hi.
( chuckles )
What is all this?
Cameron broke the TV,
so Daddy bought a new one.
Isn't it so big?
Yeah, it sure is, baby.
Hey, how was it?
Oh, it was great.
Really great.
I feel clearer.
Hey, how many of those
have you had?
Only this one.
- She broke the TV, huh?
- Yeah, long story.
Okay.
Is she home?
Well, she--
she went out--
she went out late
and I didn't hear
her come in.
Cam. Cameron.
Hold up, Donna.
She could be asleep.
( knocks )
Cam?
Cam.
Oh, my God.
( static hissing )
- Cameron over radio:
Gordon?
- Ow!
- Cameron?
- It works!
You weren't in
the office today.
Yeah, well, I needed a day
to put this thing together.
Why didn't you tell us
you moved out?
I got married.
( laughing )
No, I'm serious.
I got married to Tom
back in Texas.
Wow.
That's incredible.
I'm really happy
for you.
Thanks.
I'm happy, too.
( static hissing )
I didn't know you were gonna
be in this thing today.
I'm not.
I postponed the depo.
We need to talk.
Have a seat.
No purchases
and no promises.
That's what we said.
This morning
I got a copy of a fax
from the NSFNET lawyers
came across my desk.
So when
I called Mitch Klowden
for clarification,
he said
that the two of you
had a lovely conversation
this weekend and that
we're now in business.
Come on, Ken,
just sit down.
You're done.
I gathered the board
this morning
and we voted to remove
your executive authority
and kill the NSFNET deal.
Ken.
Of course you're more
than welcome to quit,
but we plan to enforce
the four-year noncompete.
So if I was you,
I'd just keep showing up
for work, Mr. MacMillan.
Just sit up in that
office of yours like Buddha
on the goddamn mountain
dispensing pearls of nonsense
to the tech press,
but you will never
spend another
MacMillan Utility dime,
launch another project
or give another order.
And before you even dream
about running a fire hose
into the bullpen
or some other such bullshit,
I would meditate on
the Joe MacMillan clause
our lawyers
had such fun drawing up.
One destructive
move from you,
and every point of equity
you got goes up in smoke.
Let me know
what you decide.
Bruce:
State your name.
Joe MacMillan.
And your title and place
of business, please.
Founding CEO,
MacMillan Utility.
And in your
capacity as CEO,
do you often review
outside submissions
for software ideas?
No, never.
All product development
is done in-house, then?
Yeah, yeah.
Walk me through
that process, please.
Mr. MacMillan?
- I stole it.
- What?
- Turn that off.
Turn it off.
- Don't.
I, Joe MacMillan,
stole the code
to the security software
from Gordon Clark.
Everything this company
is built on is his.
( music playing )