( knocking on door )
Hi, hi.
Welcome to California.
- Friendly state.
- Yeah.
Hey...
we're married.
Hmm.
All right.
No, no, no, no.
No, wait.
I want to do this
right, okay?
- So--
- Oh, no!
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Yes, yes!
- Okay.
- Don't. Put me down.
Okay. I'm trying
to be romantic, okay?
Just-- just
for the record,
this is my house,
you're unemployed,
and this is an absurd,
sexist tradition.
- Ouch.
- What?
I was just kidding
about that employed thing.
I know, I know.
I think I--
I think I pulled
something.
( sighs )
Can we cross
the threshold together
like not crazy people?
- Okay.
- That was easier.
- Mmm.
Good call...
Mrs. Rendon.
You're welcome,
Mr. Howe.
( keys clicking )
( key beeps )
( phone rings )
- Man: It's me.
- Hey, Joe, I got
the login set up.
It just leads
to a blank directory,
but our network
is officially live.
- Ryan, I'm out.
- Wait, out? Out of what?
MacMillan Utility.
which means NSFNET
is paused.
How-- how-- how is that
even possible? It's--
I'll explain later.
What I need is for you
to go in tomorrow
like nothing happened
because you're
gonna be fired.
The less you know,
the better,
and if anyone asks,
we never talked.
Ah, Mr. Ray. Let's chat.
Hey, Bruce.
It's Gordon.
What is this?
Bootleg "Top Gun"?
Better. Just watch.
I want to hear you
watch it.
( whirrs )
...founding CEO
of MacMillan...
Oh, jeez.
These things
are bad enough
when I'm there.
What am I watchin'
this for?
Bruce:
I don't wanna spoil it.
- Watch.
- No. Never.
- Man: What?
- Man #2: Turn it off.
Don't.
I, Joe MacMillan,
stole the code
to the security software
from Gordon Clark.
Everything this company
is built on is his.
Holy shit.
Bruce:
That's what
I wanted to hear.
I talked
to the partners,
and we think
this is worth
at least 25 mil.
You hear me?
Gordon?
Y-yeah. Yeah.
( footsteps approaching )
Donna:
Gordon, we're gonna
be late.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, everything's
great.
( "People Going Nowhere"
playing )
♪ Above the highway
and below the sky ♪
♪ A young child
sees cars go by ♪
♪ On any bridge
he can be found ♪
♪ On any street
in any town ♪
( phone ringing )
♪ He don't complain
and he doesn't shift... ♪
- ( music fades )
- ( ringing continues )
Donna:
I was thinking
of adding
a wedding ring
customization.
Heard your avatar
could maybe use one.
Hmm.
Well, that took Gordon
longer than I thought.
Is it okay for me
to say I'm happy for you?
You can say that.
This is silly.
We should celebrate.
When does Tom get here?
Uh, um...
he got here
this morning.
Well, then...
what are you doin'
tonight?
( theme music playing )
( beeping )
( door closes )
So, how bad is it?
"Mr. MacMillan
knew from the start
the Citadel software
would never remain free.
He wanted to reap
the PR benefits
and worry
about the fallout
from the lie later."
- Jesus.
- It's the first shot
in what's gonna be
a very ugly war.
I just have to
return volley.
What happened with Ken
when you went in?
I want
the blow-by-blow.
- I did what you
told me...
- Mm-hmm.
which was
to say nothing,
which was easy
because I know nothing.
Good. Now that you're
out of there, we can--
But Ken
didn't fire me.
What? Why not?
What did he offer you?
He didn't
offer me anything.
Not yet.
It's probably best
if we don't talk
or see each other
until this is over.
Okay.
Look, Ryan,
you're the weak link
in all this.
He knows the only way
to get to me
is through you.
Tom:
So, I'm 10 minutes away
from going bowling--
and I don't
even like bowling--
but, anyway,
there's a knock
at the door.
And I-- I open it.
I'm thinking it's
that weird neighbor
asking if his Burmese python
is loose in my yard again.
But, no, it's Cameron,
and she has this
look on her face.
I'll never forget it.
What happened next?
( laughs )
Okay, so you had
the honeymoon
before the wedding.
- Mm-hmm.
- Ha!
( coughs )
And, uh,
how did you propose?
- Technically, I didn't.
- Yeah, I proposed to him.
- Mmm, no.
- Donna: Mm-hmm?
Technically,
you didn't either.
- Yes, I did.
- No.
Yeah, at some point,
Cam said...
"I wish it could be
like this forever."
And I said,
"Uh, it could be."
And she said,
"But you won't move
to California."
And, um, yeah.
And then he said,
"I won't move
to California
for a girlfriend,
but I would move
there for my wife."
And the next day we found
a Justice of the Peace.
Oh, my God.
Gordon, isn't that
romantic?
What?
Tom and Cameron's story.
Right.
Um, congratulations.
- Okay.
- Thanks. Cheers.
So, um,
you gonna come
work at Mutiny?
Uh, actually, no.
We decided
that's what killed things
last time, so--
you know, mixing
a relationship with work.
Really?
And by that,
I mean that lots
of couples do that,
and it's great.
It's just-- it's just
really not for us.
But I'm gonna
swing by on Wednesday
to say hi to the guys.
I cannot wait to see
the looks on their faces
when they hear.
- They're gonna be shocked.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, Bos has really
kept this under his hat.
Hmm.
Ahem.
( faint barking )
Bos.
Look, I know full well
I should've come in
last night.
I'm listening.
Have you heard
of the Midas Touch?
Well, I got the...
opposite of that.
I'm on the outs
with my ex-wife
and my son--
hell, practically
everybody I did business
with back in Texas.
And to top it all off,
I did 14 months
in a federal prison.
I thought
you should know that...
before I cross
this threshold.
La Tuna, right?
Outside El Paso,
medium security?
You really think
I'd go into business
with a company
and not do background checks
on all of its key players?
So, you think of me
as a "key player"?
( chuckles )
Just give me
the damn flowers
and stop making problems
where there aren't any.
( water splashes,
stops )
Look, I just--
I wanted to--
Donna, look,
we weren't keeping it
just from you, okay?
Tom's mom
only found out
last Friday.
Oh. No, I get it.
It must have been fun
having a secret
nobody knew about.
Yeah, a little.
Would have been nice
to get a heads up
you were moving out,
though.
- The girls really miss you.
- Yeah, I regret that.
Look, it's just,
I...
haven't had
the easiest time
trusting you lately.
No, I know.
I think
that's probably
because I lied
to you.
I hate it.
It's been uncomfortable
and awful,
and I just--
I hate it.
Yeah.
( exhales )
I wanna trust you
again.
I do. I-- I-- I want
things to go back
the way
they used to be
between us.
I miss it.
I miss it, too.
So, where does that
leave us?
Can we just
start over?
( sighs )
Yeah.
Yeah, let's just...
have a fresh start.
- A fresh start.
- Yeah.
So, in the spirit
of complete honesty,
I've been giving it
a lot of thought,
and I really think
we should go public.
Okay. Well, I'm not
completely opposed to it.
- You're not?
- No.
I mean, we're in
the land of the IPO.
If I wasn't open to it,
I would've just stayed
in Texas.
Imagine having
the resources
to take the company
wherever we wanna go.
Yeah, I have
a pretty big
imagination.
I'm counting on it.
Donna, you're here.
So, after last night,
I haven't been able
to stop thinking
about all the things
we can do
to upgrade Mutiny
before the IPO.
I wrote down
some ideas,
and I think we should
get started right away.
- Oh, wow.
There's a lot here.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
It's like once I started,
the floodgates opened.
Well, you've obviously
put a lot of thought
and effort into this.
I did, yeah.
It totally reconfigures
Mutiny and SwapMeet
while returning them
to their roots,
excising everything that's bad
and keeping what's good.
Oh, and, yeah,
it takes us beyond
the Commodore
onto other platforms
which we have to do.
That became obvious
around 5:00 a.m.
Other platforms, right.
How long do you
see that taking?
A year.
Maybe two.
But the goal is
to do it right.
Right?
I'm sure everything that
you've outlined here is great.
I am.
But we can't afford
to wait two years.
Sure we can.
The timeframe for the IPO
is three months.
Three months?
No one ever
said anything
about three months.
Why is that suddenly
the magic number?
Because we have
an acquisition offer
in hand.
People are paying
attention to us right now.
But what we have
right now is broken.
What we have right now,
CompuServe thinks is worth
$20 million.
Yes, but if we make
the improvements
the way I know we can,
we'll be worth
$100 million.
I thought we were
in agreement on this.
We still can be.
Okay, look,
I really hate
to play this card,
but as head
of the company,
I'm saying
that we'll need
to put the brakes
on any IPO
until we get
our house in order.
Okay, how about this?
I will read this
more closely
to get a better
understanding of what
you have in mind--
Great. Okay.
And if there's anything
you don't understand,
just ask me.
Um, I promise,
this is the way to go.
( sighs )
I just got off
the phone with "Forbes"
and it doesn't sound
like a generous piece.
They're asking me
questions about WestGroup,
questions about Cardiff,
questions about IBM.
( knocking on door )
Listen,
they've clearly
got an angle
and it is not one
that is favorable to me.
- I'm calling you back.
- ( phone beeps )
I guess you talked
to your lawyers.
Wow. This is...
not what I expected.
I sure do love
that couch.
I take it
you used a designer?
And, hey, me and Donna
have this same vase.
- Pier 1, right?
- It's not a vase.
I commissioned that
from Kayako Sakaniwa,
a Tokyo artist.
- Hmm.
- She calls it
"Serenity."
Gordon,
I imagine you have
some questions...
- beyond the decor.
- Not really.
You obviously wanted
to get fired.
I've seen
that move before.
It's, uh-- it's
more complicated
than that.
Yeah?
Shocker.
Man, this is one
kick-ass view.
You can see
the bridge from here.
I'll bet you
get back every dollar
you put into this place.
Hell, I might even
buy it from you--
the furniture,
the Serenity vase--
the whole
kit and caboodle.
I never wanted you
not to profit.
"I, Joe MacMillan,
stole the code
to our security software
from Gordon Clark
of Clark Computers.
Everything
I've earned is his."
It's the most truthful thing
you've ever said.
Honestly, I was moved.
I never figured you
for a sore winner.
Me, either,
but it's nice to know
we can still
surprise ourselves.
So, what do you say
we cut through the bullshit
and you just tell me
what your angle is
in all this?
The truth is--
and this is
the truth--
I have come
across something
that I am convinced is--
well, it's something
that I really believe in,
and we'll leave it
at that.
But I couldn't convince
my board of its value,
so I ignored them,
I moved forward,
and just like that,
I lost my company.
I was out of moves,
and then it occurred to me,
what if it wasn't
my company?
So, you screw over
your evil corporate overlord
by parachuting
your stake out to me.
Okay, I get that...
sort of.
How do you come out on top
in this scenario?
I don't.
Everything I had
is yours.
If you feel like
I deserve a percentage,
well, that is
entirely up to you.
So, your plan was for me
to just give you the money?
After you stole
everything from me?
You wrote the code,
agreed,
but I offered you
partnership twice,
and you turned me down
twice.
I have to think
that you're not so myopic
that you can't see
that I might be entitled
to a little return
for turning it into
what I've turned it into.
This is
an interesting piece.
And whose work
is this?
Joe:
Mine.
Gordon, to be clear,
you don't have to
give me anything.
Thanks for making
that clear.
But I built
an entire company
and I've just
handed you everything.
All I am asking for
is basically a finder's fee.
Joe, I really do
like this piece.
What do you call it?
It's an abstract.
Yeah?
'Cause it seems to me
like one of
those paintings
that the more
you look at it,
the more it seems
to come into focus.
Gordon, I know
this is a leap of
faith on my part,
but faith is somethin'
I'm workin' on.
Faith is a--
faith is
a valuable thing.
I'd just look
for somewhere else
to place it.
Thanks for
the company, Joe.
- ( doorbell rings )
- Donna.
Is everything okay?
Cameron's gone off
the deep end
and I don't know
what to do.
She came in
today with this
Mutiny manifesto
that will kill
the IPO.
And she's
committed to it.
She did everything
but nail it to my forehead.
Maybe I should
take the night
to read this over.
Why wait?
Why not read it now?
I can wait.
Because I think
she's tryin' to stop you
from figurin' out
I'm here.
Oh! Bos!
I-- hi.
- Oh, hi.
- ( chuckles )
It's a relatively
recent development.
But if you're
worried about
Cameron finding out,
I haven't
talked to her
in over a month.
So, say what
you came to say.
- This is a lot.
- Yeah.
- How long to implement?
- A year. Maybe two.
That's a long time
to wait.
Why is she
against the IPO?
She's not, and
that's what makes it
so frustrating,
but it's what happens
with Cameron--
and, Bos,
you can back me up--
she gets
in her own way.
It's a little more
complicated than that,
but I suppose
that's part of it.
So, what do you
want to do?
I don't know.
Cameron acts like
she's majority shareholder,
but she's not.
She's got more votes
than anyone,
but not more votes
than everyone.
I'd prefer you
to find common ground.
Are you sure you can't?
Just this morning
you were telling me
what a wonderful time
you had celebrating
her marriage,
how you were excited
to start a new chapter.
Right, and then
she comes in and
dumps this on me.
Back up a beat.
Cameron got married?
Oh, Bos,
I assumed you knew.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
Wasn't your news
to tell.
Love what you've done
with the place.
Drinks with Diane?
Diane, no drinks.
( sighs )
It's Cameron.
She changed her mind
about the IPO.
What?
She wants to kill it?
That is not
her intent,
but if she has her way,
it will be the result.
Well, sorry
to hear that.
Nothing's settled yet,
but moving forward
means getting
all the equity owners
to overrule her.
We've got 35%,
and then there's
Diane and Bos
and Doug and Craig.
And Cameron has no idea
this is happening?
Nothing is happening.
It's all talk at the moment,
but I have to explore
every option.
We don't own 35%
of the company.
- Yeah, sure we do.
- No, you own 25%
and Clark Computers owns 10%
for buying the mainframe.
And Clark Computers,
i.e., me,
doesn't like the idea
of blindsiding Cameron
and shoving this IPO
down her throat.
( stammers )
That's-- that is--
just a gross
mischaracterization. I--
Donna, if you
pull this move,
I guarantee you
she'll see it
as an act of war.
and you will cross a line
that you cannot uncross.
So, don't kid yourself.
It's been a long day.
I'm going to bed.
Did you ever
witness Mr. MacMillan
talking
to Gordon Clark?
Nope.
Did Mr. MacMillan ever
confide any plans he had
with Gordon Clark?
No.
( sniffs )
Don't you find it odd,
the day we eighty-sixed
NSFNET
and we shit-canned Joe
he finds religion
and says Gordon invented
the software
this company's built on,
giving his
ex-partner,
the one suing him,
everything?
Or maybe
you didn't know.
Maybe Joe didn't
tell you that part.
And I always assumed
that you were involved.
They didn't cut you
out of the deal, did they?
Ah, no need to answer.
Look, I'm sorry, kid.
It's bigger than you.
You're just a pawn
that Joe sacrificed
in the end game,
which means that
you're useless to us.
You're probably
useless to him, too.
So...
that's it.
It's time
for you to go.
- So, I'm fired?
- Uh, yes.
Good.
Mr. Clark?
They're ready
for you.
Gordon, what are you
doing here?
Hey, Ryan.
You were right.
That thing that you
and Joe were working on?
It's gonna be huge.
( door opens )
( door closes )
So, Mr. Clark, regardless
of what Mr. MacMillan
thinks he got
away with,
we plan to fully
challenge the veracity
of his confession.
Hey, listen, I think
we can speed things up
without the lawyers.
I mean,
I don't have mine.
What do we say
you lose yours?
You're not really
gonna try to convince me
that you
and Joe didn't talk
about this, right?
I'm not gonna
try and convince you
of anything.
I'm here
to offer you a deal
that will
make that question
irrelevant.
Now, my lawyers say
I'm looking at a floor
of 25 million.
- Your lawyers are dreaming.
- I'm willing to take
10% of that,
along with the equipment
that Joe bought
and the deals
that he made for NSFNET.
Even if I wanted
to make that deal,
I can't just hand you
a government contract.
I mean, I could trade you
the infrastructure,
but you would have to
chase that bid.
No, I think
for 20 million,
you can make a call
to the sector chief
and make that happen.
Or I could just sue you
and keep it all.
Yeah, you could,
but you'll lose,
and I think
you know that.
We do it my way,
I'm giving you
everything that you want
in exchange for
nothing you care about.
Hmm. One thing
sticks in my craw.
We make this deal,
you turn around and give
Joe everything he wants
and that son of a bitch
wins again.
And what
makes you think
you're the only
one in this room
that wants to stick it
to Joe MacMillan?
Okay, let's
get this over with.
Remember to detach
Arki from me
when he uses this
as an excuse
to hug me past
a socially acceptable
amount of time.
I got it,
all right?
Let's go fry
some coders' circuits,
Mrs. Howe-Rendon.
- No.
- Rendon-Howe?
- We'll figure it out.
- Okay.
Ahem.
( "Sound Salvation"
playing )
- Tom?
- Rendon!
- Dude!
- What are you doin' here?
- Man: Whoa!
- Hey, man!
The prodigal son
returns.
Tom the Bomb!
Arki:
Finally, a real
coding lead.
How long
you here for, Rendon?
Uh, kind of
indefinitely.
- No.
- Wait a minute. What?
- Yeah, we got married!
- When did this happen?
A couple weeks ago
in Texas.
- You're not
pregnant, are you?
- Do I look pregnant?
Bodie:
Why wasn't I invited?
- Come here, you.
- Oh, God.
Come on.
- So happy for you.
- Okay, all right.
- Thank you.
- You're a very lucky man.
( men cheering )
Here's to Mutiny's
first official marriage!
May it a be long
and happy one.
( applause )
Cameron:
Okay, who wants some of that?
Arki:
Oh, yeah.
Man:
This looks great.
Carl: Bodie,
would you stop drinking
out of the bottle, dude?
Just stop drinking
out of the bottle.
Come on, man.
- I bet I can finish it.
- You have to leave
room for cake.
- No--
- Look it.
- ( crowd groans )
- What, dude?
( whistling )
CQ! CQ!
Hey.
- Hi.
- Congratulations.
Have some cake.
It's supermarket bought,
but that's the best kind.
Chemical goodness.
( chattering )
Hey, uh...
I need to talk
to you.
- Okay.
- Not here.
Yeah.
( music fades )
Donna wants to move
forward with the IPO...
with or without you.
Oh.
( sighs )
Okay.
Tough titties.
I don't want to,
and it's my company.
You're the plurality
shareholder.
You own the most.
But if she gets
everyone else
with a stake
in this company
to side with her,
she can overrule you.
Okay.
Um, Doug and Craig
will obviously
jump at the chance
to screw me.
But even if she manages
to convince Diane,
that's still
leaves you and Bos.
Game over.
It leaves Bos.
My vote's
gotta be with her...
even if I'm against it.
I'm sorry.
She's out there
throwing me a party.
and you're
gonna side with that
lying, two-faced, bi--
Careful, okay?
That's my wife.
Lucky you.
Cam.
( "Quiet Place" playing )
- ( music continues )
- ( crowd chattering )
♪ Follow me down to ♪
♪ A quiet place... ♪
( laughing )
- Yeah, there's just--
- Cameron!
Congratulations.
I'm so happy
for the two of you.
Yeah, thanks.
Can I borrow you?
( keypad beeping )
( line ringing )
Joe:
Hello?
I have to ask you
something,
and I need you to be
completely honest with me,
because I don't know
what to believe anymore.
So, don't lie
to me, okay?
What do you want
to ask me?
Did you plan
this whole thing
with Gordon?
Are you moving forward
with NSFNET
- and cutting me out?
- No, of course not.
Where did you get
an idea like this?
( sighs )
- ( keys clicking )
- ( phone ringing )
( ringing stops )
( keys clicking )
I need something
from you,
and I know things
have been super awkward
between us
since we got back
from Texas.
I should
have said something,
but I didn't.
I mean,
you didn't either,
but that's not
the point right now.
The point is,
I know it's not cool
to ask for something
when there's this
other thing between us,
but I really, really
need your help right now.
When were you
gonna tell me?
Bos, I just
found out myself.
I didn't know
Donna was gonna try
an end run around me.
About your marriage.
- Oh.
- Look, Cam,
I know you don't think
of me as a father.
You made that clear.
That's okay.
You're gonna feel
the way you wanna feel.
But it won't stop me
thinkin' of you
as a daughter.
So, tell me
what to do.
First off, don't make
this thing with Donna
any bigger than it is.
You two have a difference
of opinion, that's all.
The only reason
I'm here in the first place
is because of you.
I love you
and I owe you.
But it's not
just your company.
Not anymore.
You got-- you got
a special kind of talent,
sweetheart.
But when you march to
the beat of your own drum,
you risk
losin' the band.
Lay out your vision.
Find a way
to work with her.
You two need each other.
( sighs )
- Hey, Bos?
- Hmm?
I got married.
( chuckles )
Congratulations.
( keys clicking )
( sighs )
Whew.
( whirrs )
( crackles )
You do realize
you have a party going on?
This can't wait?
No. Please sit down.
( music playing )
Ahem.
I've had some concerns
about Mutiny's
direction,
concerns I haven't
effectively expressed.
That's on me.
Things
are moving fast,
faster than I ever
imagined they would.
It's an exciting time.
But we are
at a crossroads
and we have a decision
to make... together.
I know you all want
to move forward on the IPO.
I do, too.
But I don't think
rushing into it is in
our best interests.
- Can I say a quick word?
- Mm-hmm.
The company is valued
for what it is
and does right now.
The market likes Mutiny,
but in a year or two,
or however long it takes
to implement the changes
you have in mind,
who knows?
We can't count
on tomorrow's landscape
looking like today's.
Mutiny isn't sustainable
as it exists now.
Our whole user base
is tied to the Commodore 64.
We need to diversify
to other platforms
in order to grow.
And isn't that
what Wall Street likes?
Growth?
The kind of investment
that I'm talking about
in time and money
will pay off
and smart investors
will see that.
Your ideas are good,
Cameron,
and some of them
are even great.
And I want to
explore them with you,
all of them.
- Mm-hmm.
- But why can't
we do that
after we've gone
public?
We don't have to wait
to try and make
something perfect.
Perfect is
the enemy of good,
and Mutiny is very,
very good right now
as it is.
Donna, have you been
on SwapMeet lately?
It's like
an 8-bit mall.
It's lost what made it
a community.
We need to make it
feel alive again
or people
are going to leave
and we'll just be hosting
a bunch of tacky businesses
- selling junk
to nobody.
- But--
Please.
We can't afford
to be naive here.
If we put off
these changes,
we won't be able to
make them the right way.
You mean your way.
I mean, we'll be
so focused on PE ratios
and shareholder value,
that we won't
be able to innovate
and respond quickly.
Mutiny won't be
Mutiny anymore.
We'll lose
the company's soul.
Donna:
Say we do it your way.
What happens if your ideas,
good as they are,
don't work
or backfire?
We risk losing
our current valuation.
Going public doesn't mean
we stop innovating.
We can continue
to experiment and
improve as we go,
especially with someone
as brilliant as you
leading the way.
- Don't patronize me.
- I'm not patronizing you.
You're handling me
like you always do,
and I'm sick of it.
Listen,
I'm trying to explain
some very real risks
that you're not willing
to acknowledge
to actual stakeholders
in the company.
We can't afford
to be impulsive here.
You're calling me
impulsive? Wow.
What's that
supposed to mean?
I think people
are out there celebrating
what that means.
Oh, you mean
that bullshit little
party you threw
to distract me
from getting stabbed
in the back?
- Bos: Hey.
- Diane: Okay, ladies,
we are getting
off track here.
Diane, it's mostly
your thoughts coming
out of her mouth,
so I can't imagine
what you have to add
to the discussion.
Jesus! I don't know
who should be more
insulted.
Trust me,
if I'm expressing
an opinion,
it's because
I believe it.
I should trust you.
Yes, of course!
I mean, unless
you're lying now,
like you lied
about Doug and Craig.
Did you know
about that?
That when you told her
it was fine if I fired them,
she told me that
I had to keep them on?
Is that
the sort of person
that you wanna trust
with this business
going forward?
You mean
the kind of person
who actually tries
to make things work
instead of fighting
with anybody who threatens
her "savior complex"?
I get along fine
with people.
You alienate
everybody.
Says the woman
that will take any excuse
not to go home
to her husband.
- Hey.
- Why don't we see
if your marriage
lasts the year
before you start doling out
relationship advice?
- Donna?
- Enough. Enough!
Hey, this meeting
is over, all right?
My God!
You two go to
your corners,
wipe the blood
off your mouths,
- and we will revisit--
- ( slams )
( men murmuring )
This gets decided tonight.
I want a vote,
and I want it clean.
If you all decide
with Donna,
then you can go ahead
and do the IPO without me.
- I quit.
- Cameron, come on.
No!
I'm sick of this!
Go! Take a hard look
at this company
and ask yourself
who made it what it is
and who's just been
along for the ride!
Cameron,
please don't do this.
You want it?
You got it.
But I will not sit by
and watch this company die
because it's
being held hostage
by a petulant child.
If we don't move forward
with the IPO,
then you can steer this ship
into the rocks yourself,
because I am
outta here.
Okay, Bos is right.
Let's take a beat,
cool off--
Show of hands.
Who's in favor of doing
the IPO now
with all that
that entails?
You're breaking
my goddamn heart.
( sobs )
Oh.
( gasps )
( Cameron sniffles )
( sighs )
Joe?
What are you
doin' here?
Someone had to
drop off the keys.
Welcome
to your empire.
And thus concludes
the grand tour.
All right,
pay attention.
This is--
this is complicated.
Okay, this one--
this key's for
the building.
This key is for
the ladies' room,
for the men's bathroom,
and those two
are for the front door.
Thanks.
If it wasn't
gonna be me,
I'm glad it was you.
Write me
from the future.
- 49 percent.
- What?
Come run it with me...
and 49 percent
of the company's yours.
That's a cruel joke,
and quite frankly,
beneath you.
I'm serious.
49 percent.
With how this looks,
we need to be smart.
I should be
a silent partner.
Even better.
( laughs )
( knocks )
( footsteps approaching,
bolt clicks )
- Joe.
- Ryan, today is
a big day for us.
So, you've seen it
already?
- Seen what?
- So, then you don't know.
I released the source code
for MacMillan Utility's
security software
to the public.
- What are you
talking about?
- It's free, Joe.
Really free,
like we always wanted.
People can tinker with it,
they can make it better--
or worse,
that can happen, too.
The point is
MacMillan Utility
can no longer
profit off of it.
Joe:
But that's illegal.
And I released
documents to the media
proving that
MacMillan Utility
was totally on board
with charging the public
for 2.0 all along,
and they only went after you
when you tried to stop them.
Yeah, it shows
that they weren't trying
the protect people
or-- or keep them safe.
They were just
going to exploit them.
And I laid out
for the media
how you lost your job
defending your ideals.
Do you have any idea
what you've done?
Yes! I returned volley
just like you wanted.
It's gonna
take those bastards
years to recover.
They are gonna
come after you.
( sighs )
I'm not stupid, Joe.
I covered every
conceivable track.
They will
never catch me.
I am that good.
Yeah, nobody's
that good.
I am.
Yeah, we'll see.
( instrumental music
playing )