Man:
Mr. MacMillan.
We need to ask you
a few questions.
( police radio chatter )
Man #2:
...pack 'em up and label it.
Do you have any
additional computers?
You mean, do I own
another computer? No.
Do I have access
to other computers?
Sure, so do you.
You can go to your library,
you can go to
your friend's house--
Write down
all the locations
of computers
you have access to.
( radio chatter continues )
Have at it.
There's nothing there.
Yeah, that's what I said
when they came for me, too.
What the hell is that?
Oh, kid,
you've never seen
a packet sniffer?
Meet your worst enemy.
( beeping )
( continues beeping )
Sai:
Where you going?
I'm just, um--
I'm just gonna go
grab a bite to eat.
They told you not to leave.
What was that thing
that they were shoving
into the phone jack?
Sai:
You-- you didn't
do anything, right?
Hey, what should I tell them
if they come back?
Just don't say anything.
( theme music playing )
Joe:
Have a good morning.
( whistling )
( stops whistling )
Hey, what the hell
was that?
The FBI.
God damn it, Joe.
They're looking for Ryan.
He, uh--
he did a stupid thing.
He-- he released
the source code
for MacMillan Utility's
anti-virus software online.
- You've got to be kidding.
- All of it.
It's a violation
of the CFAA--
They think you did it.
I know what
you're gonna say.
It's what everyone's
gonna say, Joe.
- Please, listen.
- Stop, stop!
Stop.
Look me in the eye
and tell me you had nothing
to do with the leak.
I had nothing
to do with it.
All right.
Then I'm all in.
All right?
We'll figure
this out together.
While it's true
that the pace
of Mutiny's growth
has slowed somewhat,
multi-platform expansion
is not the only solution.
Rather,
Mutiny is employing
a number of strategies
which, taken together,
promise a second quarter
earnings uptick--
Stop. You can't say that.
It's not
in the prospectus.
Well, I have
to say something.
They can see
that that user numbers
are plateauing.
The company's laudable
record of growth
is fully documented
in the prospectus.
That sounds like
I'm hiding something.
You can't hype the stock.
Well, what's the point
of doing this road show
if all I can say
is read the prospectus?
So, they read
the prospectus.
Well, there are things
that I want to clarify.
The prospectus should be
a living document.
- Bosworth: Well, it's not.
- Diana: Sorry, SEC rules.
Look,
you're doing great.
The whole point
of coming to these
smaller firms first
is so that you can
work out the kinks
before we take it
to the big guns in
Boston and New York.
I thought it went
pretty well last night,
don't you think?
No, I think they were
all underwhelmed.
Hey, I read the room
as I see it.
You did fine.
Fortunately,
there isn't much
investment capital
for tech in Denver.
Look, everybody
hates this process,
and everybody
gets through it.
So, come on,
tell me about
Mutiny's founder
Cameron Howe.
I understand
she's no longer
with the company.
Cameron is one
of the most talented coders
in Silicon Valley.
She gave her heart
and soul to Mutiny,
- and her spirit
is still very much--
- Bosworth: Oh, please!
It sounds like
you're eulogizing
the family dog.
That's what we agreed
I'd say.
It doesn't pass
the smell test.
Donna:
Do you have
a better suggestion?
Something with a faint hint
of truth to it, maybe?
Oh, so I should say
that she's a temperamental
narcissist
with self-destructive
tendencies who doesn't
work with others?
Well, at least
it sounds like you mean it
when you say that.
I'm sorry that
there's no pretty way
to talk about this.
But just a reminder,
you voted for it, too.
Yes, I did, under duress,
as I recall.
Nobody wanted it.
It's just what happened.
And yet, here we are.
Look, I'm just trying
to help out here.
Unless you just want me
to go get the coffee?
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
Hey.
Are you leaving already?
Tom:
Yeah, I figured I'd wait
till my second week
till I start
showing up late.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Hey, can you,
uh, run to the store,
get some candy for
the trick or treaters?
- Mmm.
- Cam, they're kids,
they want candy,
and you should try
to get out a little bit.
- Can you do it?
- Mmm, no.
Oh.
- I love you.
- Love you.
Mmm.
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
...Winner's Circle
over here.
That's where you go
to win most of the money,
though you can win
some bonus money
at your chairs over there--
10 and $25,000
to crack over there.
- ( buzzing )
- These are the subjects
in the first game today.
We've got "Water,
Water Everywhere";
"Round And Round";
"Remember When";
"Keep Them Sealed";
"We'll Be Right Back"--
sounds like
commercial messages.
I don't know what that is,
but that sure sounds like
what it is.
"King Kong's Kid";
and we have...
( buzzing )
( buzzing intensifies )
( over phone )
It's Ryan Ray.
This deal
between Joe and Gordon,
it's bullshit.
I was there
from the beginning.
The network wouldn't
exist without me.
And I'm better
than Gordon Clark
by a magnitude of 20.
Gordon wants to roll over
for Cisco on TCP/IP upgrades.
It's so short-sighted,
he's a joke!
- That's who you're
in business with.
- ( button clicks )
I don't know
what to say, Mitch.
I'm sorry you had
to find out this way.
I was too invested
in this project to
just walk away.
Listen, Joe, we like you.
You believed
in the network.
Hell, you walked away
from your own company
when your board
voted against us.
But Ryan--
let's face it,
Ryan doesn't sound
like a guy who's gonna
keep his mouth shut.
His next call
could be to my boss.
Ryan would
never do that.
Well, regardless,
we can't work with someone
who's being investigated
for computer fraud,
who blatantly violated
major legislation that
went into effect this year.
Joe didn't do
anything wrong.
Mitch:
I'm not saying he did.
But until we find the person
who is responsible,
you two need to stay away
from each other.
And this network contract
is frozen.
How did Ryan know
that we were working
together?
Hmm? Down to the details
of my negotiations
with Cisco?
He must be reading
our emails.
He built the network.
He knows how to get inside
better than anyone.
Well...
we gotta turn him in.
No, there must be
another way.
What are you talking about?
Did you hear the tape?
- The contract's frozen.
- I can't do that to him.
Oh, Christ, Joe.
He's my friend.
I thought
I was your friend.
No?
( screams )
( doorbell rings )
All right.
Jesus, I'm coming.
Kids:
Trick or treat!
Ooh.
You're the first non-princess
I've seen for hours.
I hate princesses.
Me, too.
You only got one thing.
Yeah.
Take it or leave it.
Alf.
Shoo.
( knocking on door )
Oh.
( laughs )
Well...
it's a very tall child
dressed as Joe MacMillan.
Batman was sold out.
Can I come in?
Yeah.
( TV playing
in background )
It's a good color.
It's a work in progress.
So, what's going on?
I assume you're not
here for the candy?
I've got a problem.
It sounds like you got
a lot of problems.
I mean, unless it's true
there's no such thing
as bad publicity.
I'm--
I'm not responsible
for the leak.
I, yeah, figured.
You know,
clearly it was someone
with actual skills.
I just mean
obviously it was Ryan.
I need to find him
and he's off the grid.
The feds are calling me
every week.
I bet, probably because
every chat room online
thinks you're some kind of
8-bit Robin Hood.
I didn't make
Ryan do this.
Yeah, I know.
It's hard to make
Ryan do anything.
If you could send out
a kind of flare--
I mean, Ryan's talented,
but if anyone can track him...
Oh...
are you gonna
turn him in?
No, I'm worried
about him.
He's running out
of options.
- ( screaming on TV )
- Man: Oh, my God!
Sorry.
( TV turns off )
( laughs )
How are you doing?
Never better,
as I'm sure you can see.
Well, look at us.
Two unemployed CEOs
both ousted
from our companies.
Mine's toast
and yours is going public.
Mm-hmm.
Gordon told me.
Yeah.
I'm working
with Gordon now.
Really?
( laughs )
Now, there's a twist.
You were right.
I needed to give him credit
and include him,
and we're working
on something
that I'm really
excited about.
So, uh, thank you
for that.
Yeah, well...
thank you.
Oh.
Hmm.
Him.
Well, you picked
a good guy.
He's lucky.
No, I'm pretty sure
right now I'm just
making him miserable.
( laughs )
Oh, I haven't
seen one of these
since I was a kid.
That's scary.
Yeah.
I had to zap it
'cause of Halloween.
I didn't want those
little wieners getting stung.
Yeah.
I'd appreciate
your help with Ryan.
- ( door opens )
- Hey, Joe.
Here.
Trick or treat.
( laughing )
( ringing )
Clark residence.
Hi, sweetheart.
How's your costume?
Good.
A little itchy.
And my teacher said
I have to call my spear
a walking stick.
Why?
I don't know.
Kids aren't supposed
to have spears?
Well, can they have
imaginary spears?
I don't know.
I didn't ask that.
Well, you tell her--
Daddy,
Mommy's on the phone!
Haley?
Have the best time,
okay, sweetheart?
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How's it going?
- Pretty good.
I think I did all right today.
How are things over there?
Great.
Everything's great.
- Joanie: No, a braid.
- Is that Joanie?
Can I talk to her?
Hey, Mom wants
to talk to you.
Not while you're braiding.
It'll be all lopsided.
- All right.
- That's okay.
Just tell her
to have fun,
all right?
What's she going as?
Joan Montana.
( laughing )
Take pictures, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Will do.
Gordon,
I-- I miss you.
Yep, miss you, too.
Hurry up, Daddy.
( dial tone )
"Blue Dream" playing
♪ We go out,
the people are starin' ♪
♪ No sense, you don't
know how to deal with it ♪
♪ You wake up back in bed
with a blue dream ♪
♪ A blue dream ♪
♪ I went down to the club
on a Saturday... ♪
Gordon: Two kids,
three-ring circus.
Haley's like
a tiny prosecutor.
She kept coming down here
to offer evidence against
her sister.
Yeah, Joanie's too scary
to convict.
Her teenage self
is lurking on the horizon
like some post-apocalyptic
ravager.
Ravager, huh?
You have no idea.
So, um, I was hoping
you had heard some news.
I haven't heard from him.
Oh.
Can I ask you
a question?
Were--
were you and Ryan, um,
ever, uh...
you know.
What?
Um, did you...
you know...?
You know?
What?
You know, were--
were you, you know,
more than... friends?
You know?
I never had those
feelings for Ryan.
Ah.
Actually,
he kind of
reminds me of you.
Oh, come on,
please don't say that.
That's-- I don't know
how to respond to that.
- Uh...
- ( laughing )
Stop messing with me.
You should move forward
with the NSFNET project alone.
Wh-what?
What are you talking about?
I don't want
to hold you back.
You're not holding me back.
You're helping me.
Gordon,
Mitch was pretty clear
about this.
- Joe, please don't do this.
- You know how these
things work.
- If you miss the window--
- I can't do it alone.
Yes, you can.
Don't sell yourself short.
I'm sick, Joe.
- I'm sick.
- What-- what the hell
does that mean?
- ( telephone rings )
- Hang on real quick.
- Gordon?
- Hang on, I gotta get this.
- Leave it.
- Look, it could be Donna.
Just give me two secs.
Hello?
Now?
No, I got the kids. I--
All right, look, I'll--
I'll figure something out.
Yep.
( sighs )
That was Mutiny.
They need me to--
it doesn't--
we need to talk,
all right?
But right now I need
a favor from you.
You're not going anywhere
until you tell me
what's going on.
- Look, I can't.
I gotta go--
- Sit down.
Sit.
Ryan.
Ryan. Ryan!
How'd you find me?
Uh...
I put up
the "Are You Safe"
board on Mutiny.
You logged in remotely
through an FTP connection--
You wrote a software trap
alerting you to my activity,
including the university
mainlines.
( groans )
I should have
thought about that.
Hey, I'm not here
to bust you or anything.
Joe wants to help you.
I-- I want to help you.
Hey, you--
Ryan, you can't live off
Dr Pepper and Cheez-Its
forever.
Believe me, I've tried.
Where have you been?
I crashed with friends
for a while.
The cops,
they keep tracking me.
Uh, how did you know?
I could feel it.
Somebody was following me.
And-- and my buddy,
he kept getting
these weird phone calls.
Yeah.
And, um,
I took the bus
down to San Diego
and, um, stayed
with my cousin.
He's a wannabe tech guy
and a total asshole.
He said he wouldn't
rat me out, but I--
I knew he would,
you know?
I hitched a ride
back to SF.
I needed a cup of coffee
and a computer, so...
I blended in right here.
It's like I'm invisible.
Joe probably hates me now.
Oh, no.
( scoffs )
No, and even
if he is pissed,
he'll get over it.
Joe can be...
surprisingly forgiving.
Maybe it's because he's screwed
up his own life so many times.
Hey, if you don't want me
to tell him where you are,
I won't.
But he really just wants
to walk you through
your options.
He's worried about you.
And look,
I found you,
so... you can't hide
forever.
I thought you were gonna
bring the girlies along.
No.
Found a great new sitter.
Really flexible.
Well, thanks for
bailing me out.
I didn't want to worry Donna
on the eve of her big day.
Yeah.
What you gonna do
with your share of the IPO?
I don't know.
I guess I should
make some plans.
You know, they're saying
it's gonna open at 15.
Ha, 15.
Who'd have thunk it?
What are you gonna do
with your share?
Oh, stash away some
for a college fund
type of thing
for my grandson.
That is, if that's
all right with James.
Yeah?
Why wouldn't it be?
Well...
you never know
what might hit a nerve.
All right.
You talk to Cam?
No.
You?
Nope.
But...
she'll be a millionaire
tomorrow.
She can't be
too sorry about that.
- Hey, here's
to going public.
- To going public.
- ( car door opens )
- Tom: Yeah, you bet.
Thanks so much.
- ( car door closes )
- Man: No problem.
( car departs )
Well, look at you.
Waiting for me
at the front door.
Mm-hmm.
We're one apron away
from a lifelong fantasy.
( laughing )
I have a proposition
for you.
Can I show you
something first?
- Mmm, yeah.
- Okay, good.
- Okay.
It's called
the "Spacebike Chronicles."
- Okay.
- This is our hero.
She doesn't have a name.
And she's just
cruising through
the post-apocalyptic future
on her bad-ass space-bike.
And all she needs to survive
are gas, candy,
and the occasional
long, hot shower.
So, she travels
to planets and asteroids
and space stations
trying to get what she needs.
Oh! And when she arrives
at a new place,
she tries to win
one of the five senses.
Each one arms her
with a different power.
A sense of proportion
allows her to change size.
A sense of humor
allows her to fend off
most forms of attack.
A sense of self
allows her to appear
and disappear.
Okay, well,
decency doesn't give her
an actual power,
but it makes it possible
for her to win
the rarest sense of all--
common sense,
which lets her see
everything more clearly.
It's beautiful.
( laughs )
How do you win?
You don't, you just
get to keep playing.
I love it.
Come here.
Come here, come up.
Do you want to hear,
uh, the proposition?
Mm-hmm.
How do you feel
about moving to Japan?
( laughs )
What?
They want to move me up.
All the way to Tokyo.
That's perfect.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Ryan?
Why'd you lie to me?
Why'd you cut me out?
I didn't do either
of those things.
- I planned to bring you in.
- Bring me in?
I created the whole thing.
I put the code out there,
really made it free
when you didn't have
the guts
to do it yourself.
And I've been
out there ever since,
defending your name,
telling the real story.
I've been worried
about you.
Hey, sit down.
I know you're angry,
just admit it.
I'm not.
I wish you hadn't upset
the NSFNET deal.
You've made things
much harder.
But that
is less important
than knowing
that you're okay.
As I see it,
you've got two options.
You can turn yourself in
and own up to what you did...
or you can run.
Either way,
I will help you.
How?
If you run,
I'll give you 50 grand,
drive you to the bus station
and you can disappear.
But the network
you and I created
will disappear, too.
No, I don't want that.
I put in a call
to my lawyer.
If you turn yourself in,
you'll serve no more
than a year or two.
No, I can't.
Listen to me.
A hacker
that violates the CFAA
can't touch a computer
for at least five years--
Five years?
That's insane!
And that's
an impossible choice!
It's better than
10 years in prison.
That's the maximum.
I know it sounds
like a long time,
but you're young,
and it's like you told me,
destruction leads
to transformation.
You've got plenty of time
to reinvent yourself.
Yeah, that's what
I want to do.
Start again with you,
like when you first hired me.
We sat right here
making shit up,
writing ideas
on the board.
Okay, all right.
Fine.
Let's say I--
I do what you say
and I serve my time.
Tell me we can
still work together.
That's not possible.
But you would have done
the same thing.
You're a master
at this kind of move.
It's classic
Joe MacMillan.
I can't work with
Joe MacMillan anymore.
( chair clatters )
Fine.
I'll do this
with or without you.
I hope you do.
You're a hypocrite
and you always have been.
You don't have to
decide tonight.
I want you to sleep here
and we can talk more
in the morning.
But you need
some rest, Ryan.
I'll get some sheets
and we can make up the sofa.
( sighs )
Where would madam
like the tray?
Oh, uh,
on the bed, please.
Will there be
anything else?
No, thank you.
- ( knocks )
- Diane: Donna?
How'd you sleep?
Oh, horribly,
but I didn't
really mind.
The sheets
were so comfortable.
Have you eaten breakfast?
Oh, no, no.
I don't do breakfast
when I'm nervous.
I do.
I'm gonna be on TV
and then my company's
going public.
You're gonna be great.
You always say that.
No, you are.
You're gonna be great.
( Diane laughs )
So, just look directly
into it like it's a person.
Lynda will be able
to see you.
Her voice will come
into your earpiece.
There will be a bit
of a sound delay.
Any questions?
Five away.
All right,
come on, guys.
I wanna go
back to bed.
I know, but we gotta
get up and watch Mommy.
All right?
It's her big day.
I'll make you guys
some breakfast
in just
a little bit, okay?
All right, you guys
get on the couch.
( TV playing )
- Come on, hop up.
- ( groans )
Gotta make
some room for Daddy.
Lynda:
Welcome back
to "Financial Watch AM."
This morning we have
with us Donna Clark,
CEO of Mutiny,
a trailblazer
in the brave new world
of online shopping.
- Welcome, Donna.
- Look, it's Mommy.
Lynda:
Thanks to people
like our guest,
for the 25 million
Americans
who own
personal computers,
Christmas shopping
is just a keystroke away.
- So, Donna...
- Haley: She looks so pretty.
a woman who founded
a tech company.
You're something
of an anomaly, aren't you?
Well, actually,
Mutiny was founded
by my former partner,
Cameron Howe.
Ah, I see.
And where is he?
Uh, she is no longer
with the company.
So, it was founded
by a woman?
Yes.
Lynda:
So, how does it work,
this new e-tail phenomenon?
It's very simple, really.
Most home computers
are connected
to something
called a modem.
That's a device
which uses--
Oh, dear,
it's sounding complicated.
It isn't, really--
Bottom line--
can I buy my shoes with it?
Yes, absolutely.
We're in partnership
with several retailers and--
Lynda:
Finally, something
about computers
to get excited about.
So, how exactly
would I buy my shoes?
Donna:
Well, you would log on
to Mutiny and from the home--
We intercepted
the ticker feed
from phone lines.
Going into a bank.
And then rerouted
to the office modem.
- Ah!
- Yeah.
Well, that sounds
entirely legal.
Sure.
Okay, for the record
I had no prior knowledge
of this plan.
- ( laughter )
- Shit.
Oh, come on.
Rookie move, son.
What are you doing?
Sailboat?
Don't spend your money
before you've made it.
- Coder: What a dweeb!
- ( coders laughing )
Okay, look.
So, the companies debuting
today come out first.
Lev:
How many are there?
I don't know.
- Oh, here we go.
Here we go.
- Hey, look at that.
Bodie:
Money, money, money.
Okay, here we go.
Okay, it's a little lower
than we expected.
Just breathe.
( all sighing )
( sighs )
Joanie:
Can we call Mommy yet?
Uh, I think we're gonna
wait a little.
Do you wanna know?
Just... tell me
if it's good or bad.
( sighs )
I know
it's a morale blow.
I get it.
But it doesn't mean
that the stock
is worthless.
It's just not worth
what we thought.
It could be
the pace of our growth.
a Commodore issue.
They had
a horrible quarter.
Or just a calendar thing.
There are all sorts
of schools of--
Can I, um--
can I have a minute?
( door opens, closes )
( breathing heavily )
( knocking on door )
( knocking continues )
Mr. MacMillan,
we need to come in.
What's this about?
Was Ryan Ray
in your apartment
last night?
Yeah.
But he's gone now.
I don't know where he is.
Sir, why don't
you sit down?
( distant sirens wailing )
Gordon:
Look, Joe,
how many times
are you going to read that?
He wrote it right here
while I was sleeping.
I can't profit from this.
No.
No, it was your idea.
Okay? I'll--
I'll wait for you.
You know? I'll see
if I can stall things.
Yeah, you shouldn't
want to work with me.
The night I was--
stood out there
with Ryan,
we talked about...
God, I don't know
what I was saying.
Look, that's--
that's not why.
Jesus Christ.
I was trying to help him.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
I can't keep having
this conversation.
I'm done.
Hey, Gordon.
I'm sorry.
Are you sure you don't
want to postpone?
I don't know
if there's a funeral.
No, let's go.
Are you sure?
'Cause we can
change our flight.
Tom, I'm fine.
Okay?
I'm ready to leave
this place.
You know...
( sighs )
God, maybe...
there will be some things
that they won't have
- in Japan.
- Yeah?
Yeah, maybe I should
go to the store
and just...
make sure that we have
everything we need.
Yeah, of course.
Good idea.
You want me
to go with you?
No, I'll go.
Okay.
Ryan's voice:
"I, Ryan Ray, released
the MacMillan Utility
source code.
I acted alone.
No one helped me,
and no one told me to do it.
I did this because
'security' is a myth.
Contrary to what you might
have heard, my friends,
you are not safe.
Safety is a story.
It's something
we teach our children
so they can sleep at night,
but we know it's not real.
Beware,
baffled humans.
Beware of false prophets
who will sell you
a fake future,
of bad teachers,
corrupt leaders
and dirty corporations.
Beware of cops
and robbers...
the kind that rob
your dreams.
But most of all,
beware of each other,
because everything's
about to change.
The world is going
to crack wide open.
There's something
on the horizon.
A massive connectivity.
The barriers between us
will disappear,
and we're not ready.
We'll hurt each other
in new ways.
We'll sell and be sold.
We'll expose
our most tender selves,
only to be mocked
and destroyed.
We'll be so vulnerable,
and we'll pay the price.
We won't be able
to pretend
that we can protect
ourselves anymore.
It's a huge danger,
a gigantic risk,
but it's worth it.
If only we can learn
to take care of each other.
Then this awesome,
destructive new connection
won't isolate us.
It won't leave us
in the end so...
totally alone.
( seagulls screeching )
( waves crashing )