( drilling )
Donna Emerson,
senior partner.
My God, that does
have a ring to it,
doesn't it?
Here.
You know I like redheads,
but my God,
that new girl at reception
got a real attitude.
- She make you sign in?
- Well, she damn well did.
Hey, I'm sorry
I missed the celebration.
We had a big storm
down in the San Juans.
Wow. I never pegged you
for a Montblanc kind of guy.
Well, I ain't.
I thought it would go
with the decor.
Also got that nice
little snowflake thing
right on top.
- Thanks, Bos.
- Sure.
Jeez.
Hey, you wanna
stick around?
Maybe got downstairs,
get a cup of coffee, or--?
Oh, I would love to,
but, uh...
I gotta hit the road.
Diane's already
up at the Vineyard.
Look, anyway,
congrats.
Oh, say.
Are you going to
Comdex this year?
Uh... no.
Too much work this year.
Oh, you know,
it's a circus now.
Not like it used to be.
It's more trouble
than it's worth.
Well...
All right.
Hey, now, that's
the good stuff.
Remember,
respect the dirty bird
or fear
the kickin' chicken.
"Kickin' chicken"?
Announcer:
...16-point lead.
( overlapping, indistinct
television announcers)
Announcer:
...1:09 to go,
14 to nothing...
( overlapping, indistinct
television announcers)
( no audio )
( speed dial, phone rings )
Morning, Ray.
Mm-hmm.
Amgen's a yes,
put it on the tape.
( pen clicking )
Yeah,
I'm not interested, Ray.
Pass.
The guy's hunting elephants
but bagging pigeons, Ray.
Pass.
Pass, Ray.
What's your position
on Lam Research?
All right,
set up a limit order.
I'm not interested.
You know I'm long on telecom.
That's all.
Man:
Look, we'd just prefer
if it was you coming out,
even for one night.
Guys, you're in great hands.
Elias will make sure
that CaminoWare
is the talk of Comdex.
- Wait, wait, wait--
- And by the time
you're back in San Jose,
I'll have the table set
for your Series B financing.
How does that sound?
All right.
Well,
we should go pack.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, Jesus, guys,
I've got your Heinekens.
Whatever you do,
don't do that at Comdex.
Okay, thanks.
It was really
sweet of you.
Hey, Donna. This is
your area of expertise.
Settle a bet for me.
This fellow thinks the feds
are gonna deregulate
all of NSFNET by '91.
( chuckles )
Gordon Clark,
this here is--
Donna. Donna Emerson.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah, so I said the goddamn
federal government
can't even deliver my
Playboys without some creep
swiping them
every other month.
'93 at the earliest.
Well, there's a senator
in Tennessee.
He's a real dog with a bone
on this thing.
- Oh, you seem really
sure of yourself.
- I am.
And you know,
for a long time I wasn't.
and then this... weight
was suddenly lifted off of me.
What kind of weight
exactly?
Like someone poured cement
in a bunch of bowling balls
and then strapped
those bowling balls
onto a big fat circus man
and then he climbed
this ladder...
- And then stood
on your shoulders?
- You get it.
I do! I cut loose
a ball and chain
of my own recently.
- Mm.
- Very liberating.
So, what now?
Just casual sex and cosmos?
- Casual sex and martinis.
- Mm.
Oh, but "casual" makes
it sound boring, lazy.
I'd rather go with
"hot and dirty" sex.
Speaking of,
what are you doing later?
Mm. Hot date, sorry.
We'll settle
the bet later.
Yes, we will.
( clears throat )
Who was that?
I don't know.
So, congratulations,
it's official.
Donna Emerson.
You really couldn't stand
being a Clark, could you?
Emerson has three syllables.
It's got stature, you know?
Plus, it takes up more space
on the sign, so.
Well, my name,
your dad's name--
what's the difference?
We should probably get a move on
if we want to get our
reservation, Gordo.
Um, yeah.
Uh, Michelle,
this is Donna.
- Donna,
this is Michelle.
- Oh, of course.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
You as well.
Um, let me just
close out my tab?
Sure, yeah.
I'm gonna grab my coat.
It was--
It was nice meeting you.
Gordo?
Ms. Emerson.
She seems nice.
She is.
Hey, can you watch
Joanie on Friday?
Haley's still at space camp
and, you know,
Joanie just listens to CDs
and makes collages.
You really don't
have to do anything.
Look, Diane's
at the Vineyard,
Elias is at Comdex,
Gilson's useless,
so, the whole company's
on my shoulders.
I just thought I'd ask.
Suck it up.
It's your turn.
"The Star-Spangled Banner"
playing in background
♪ Over the land
of the free... ♪
( phone rings )
♪ And the home... ♪
- ( ringing )
- ♪ Of the brave ♪
( ringing continues )
- Yeah?
- Joe.
It's Donna.
Donna Clark.
How have you been?
You shouldn't
have this number.
All right, look,
I'll cut to the chase.
Are you going to Comdex?
What do you want, Donna?
Cameron will be there.
I want to send you
something...
to give to her--
a memo.
You want me to go to Comdex
to give Cameron...
a memo?
Just read it.
If it makes the same impression
on you as it made on me,
you'll be on
the next plane to Vegas.
If you want to get in touch
with Cameron so bad,
why are you calling me, not her?
You know why.
Joe, this thing
is perfect for her.
Just... read it.
You'll see.
I can't help you.
Good-bye, Donna.
( ringing )
( fax machine beeps )
( beeping )
( music playing )
Mrs. Howe-Rendon?
Hi.
I almost didn't
recognize you.
I expected
you'd be wearing
a leather jacket
and have a bunch
of tattoos.
Like in Space Bike.
We're different people.
Of course.
Oh.
Let's get you
set up.
( soft laugh )
They fly you all the way
out from the Orient
just for this?
Amazing.
Here it is.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
Hi, I'm Tracy.
Hi, Tracy.
They told me not to sit
on the bike because
I might crush it.
- That's probably good advice.
- ( laughs )
You've got a few minutes
to settle in before
the signing starts.
Oh, yeah.
Here's your lunch.
As you requested,
a bean and cheese burrito.
Thank you.
I've been in Japan
for four years.
Oh.
Mmm.
If I had to choose one word
to describe myself,
I guess I would say, um,
"seeker."
Yeah, you know?
And, uh...
And "giver." Yeah.
I mean,
I'm a tech professional
but I'm not just
bits and bytes.
I own a regional network
that's part of NSFNET,
which connects researchers
to the National Science
Foundation
super-computing center,
via T-1 backbone
through a Unix-based rout--
Look,
( clears throat )
let's just say
I do well for myself.
Fun is very important to me,
and listen, if, you know,
it's casual,
you know, it stays casual,
I'm okay with that.
And if it becomes something
more than casual
then I'm okay with that too.
Yeah.
And I like camping.
I really like camping.
Do-- do you like camping?
Recently, I've gotten
into fine cuisine,
uh, cooking.
But, like, really doing it.
You get to cook something,
and then you look at it,
and you think,
"I made this!"
And then you get to eat it
and then move on.
That makes me happy.
My, uh, name--
Can I look into the thing?
- Uh, my name is Gordon...
- Joanie?
number 108A-2...
Joanie, that is private.
Mm. Yeah.
Making a video
that screams
"I need to get laid"
is totally private.
"Get laid"?
Who taught you that?
Dad, I know kids
in school giving handjobs
in the parking lot.
I'm not a kid.
No, you don't.
And yes, you are.
All right.
Now, what time am I
taking you to this party?
- It starts at 9:00.
- Can I take you a little
earlier?
My date-- Okay.
I'm cooking dinner
for someone and
she'll be here at 7:30.
Yeah, but Jennifer is seeing
Child's Play 2 at 6:30
to go stalk Bobby Ostoff.
So, she probably won't
even be back until 8:30.
The party's at Jennifer's?
Mom said I could go.
Yeah, well, Mom told me
that Diane was out of town
all week.
You can't go to a party
if there aren't
any parents there.
- You know that.
- But Mom said!
Joanie, when you're
staying with me,
- I make the decisions.
- God!
- Joanie?
- Ugh!
Thanks.
Right, okay,
so I've got some
banging ideas
for Space Bike 5.
Okay, so there's this--
there's this space goldfish--
Fantastic!
So, just pay over there.
- Hi, I'm Jessica.
- Hey.
Alex.
You two going
to the Atari keynote
later?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Don't let boys like that
push their way in front of you.
- Okay.
Okay.
Can you make it out
to "Joe"?
Yeah, it's just a really
amazing culture, you know?
Do you even speak Japanese?
( speaking Japanese )
Ooh.
That means,
"I don't want the shrimp
with the heads on."
It's a very useful
phrase in Tokyo.
So, you're gonna stay?
Maybe, yeah.
It's-- I don't know,
we've really settled in.
It was weird at first.
like, alien, you know?
And that's what
Space Bike 2
was all about.
It was just,
Tom was working a ton
and I was wandering around
this strange city
feeling lost.
And then...
I don't know, one day
I just decided to give
myself over to it.
Just like that, like a--
like a switch...
flicked in your brain?
Yeah.
( laughs )
It's just,
you go through life
and you have this idea
of who you are,
and what you do,
and then...
you discover
it's total bullshit.
It's a defense mechanism,
and once you stop
defending yourself
you can be
all these other things,
and that...
- Yeah.
- seems totally cheesy.
No, it's not.
I still suck
at using chopsticks.
So, what are you
doing here?
Are you still
consulting?
I'm thinking about
getting back into that,
if the gig is right.
It's amazing how much changes
in just a few years.
And how much stays the same.
So, what do you think?
What should I see?
Oh, uh...
Well, you can skip
all the laptops.
They're just variations
on a theme.
Uh... the Microsoft booth
is "ugh."
Gates' speech is overrated.
Just get the transcript.
Oh, Phillips
just released
a recordable CD
and Adobe added some
cool stuff to this thing
called Photoshop.
So...
Yeah, great.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
( laughs )
Well, God, it was--
it was great to see you,
and, uh,
this was a lot of fun.
Wait. Are those...
those guys from '83
that had that really
terrible printer?
You convinced them
you were from IBM?
Oh!
Yeah. We bought out
their suite for the Giant.
That suite came with that
free seafood tower.
Hey, what are you doing?
Offering, uh,
fully-integrated
TypeKit compatibility
while our superior
heat sink
ensures that your...
presentation won't drown,
but rather, float...
Into the sky.
Moreover,
paper jams can scram...
( screams, laughs )
- That just happens.
- Um...
meaning that you can
sit back and relax....
And enjoy the flight--
the flight of your data,
that is,
due to transfer speeds
so fast
that you'll think
your documents were...
Come on.
Come on, Petey.
There's a little breeze.
Get your hand in front of it.
Use your backhand.
On fire.
Cool, cool, cool.
So, it's called the, uh,
the "S Printer"?
Oh, no, um... "Sprinter."
- Because it prints
really fast.
- No space.
It's kind of confusing
with the flame gag, though.
- It's a mixed metaphor.
- "S Printer" does
sound better, though.
- Doesn't it?
- Yeah. It's got
rigor behind it.
Like the R&amp;D Department
was unsatisfied
with models A through R,
and then finally,
after a lot of sweat
and tears...
We proudly bring you
version S.
Um... it's the Sprinter.
No space.
Hey, do I know you?
Here, help yourself
to a lighter.
No, just one, please.
- Oh, that's a lot.
- Good luck, guys.
- Not all of--
- She took so many.
Just one, please,
one.
( rock music
playing in distance )
( doorbell rings )
- Hey. Michelle.
- Hi. Hi.
What you got, what's--
Oh, it uh,
it says "kiss the cook"
but in binary code.
- ( laughing )
- So, uh.
Oh. Well.
It smells great.
That's the Bolognese.
You know, a lot of people
think that pasta's Italian,
but it actually
originated in China.
- Huh.
- Yeah, 1100 B.C.
You're taking me
to the party. I left
a message on Mom's service.
- She's gonna tell you
to let me go.
- Um, Joanie?
- This is Michelle.
- Hi.
Michelle, this is
my lovely daughter,
Joanie.
- Hello.
- Hey.
I, uh--
I like your shirt.
It's very... cultural.
Do you like culture?
( laughs )
What's it, um, say?
Well, "shonen"
is Japanese for "boy."
So, it means "boy knife."
Huh.
"Boy knife" means "dick."
- Hmm.
- Um, do you want some wine?
- Mm-hmm.
- ( clears throat )
Cameron:
I wonder how high
you'd have to be up
for your spit
to actually kill someone.
( laughing )
( yawning )
Okay, let's see
what we got.
Ooh.
What do you think?
Oh, I wouldn't.
They make your ass look big.
Oh, okay.
Here are the rules.
Four rows of lighters.
When it's your turn,
you can take as many
or as few as you want,
as long as they're
from the same row.
The person who ends up
with the last lighter
loses.
You wanna go first
or second?
Mm, bold.
Is there anything
on the floor catch
your eye?
No, I'm going whole hog
on the Sprinter.
Those guys really have
their finger on the pulse.
Actually it was...
it was all
pretty overwhelming.
You know,
if you look closely,
there are some diamonds
in those dorks.
( laughs )
Would you really
wish me on anyone?
You lose.
You go first this time.
Hey,
I knew what I was doing,
you know,
when we worked together.
And Mutiny took a nosedive
all on its own,
didn't need you
to screw that one up for us.
And Gordon,
would be the first to admit
that he made his own bed.
Yeah, but...
But Ryan, right?
Yeah, Tom and I were...
leaving for Japan
when we heard.
At first I was...
angry.
At you...
and at him.
And at myself...
for all these things
I never said to him.
Then I realized
there was nothing anyone
could have done about it.
Not you and not me.
- You don't know that.
- Neither do you.
You're not that powerful.
So, eventually, my anger
turned into sadness,
and...
that's fine,
that's healthy.
I mean, yes, be sad.
But Jesus,
stop blaming yourself.
I win.
This isn't about Ryan.
It's, um...
I'm just saying
I don't think you should...
deprive the world
of what you do.
Okay.
What is it that I do?
It's so hard...
to bring about
actual change.
Real change.
The whole world
conspires to stop that
from happening.
But you bring people together.
You... create change.
I think that that's...
really great.
Hey, so I have this
Atari party
that I have to go to
that would be so much
more fun if you would come
and get drunk with me.
What, so I can fend off
your groupies?
Exactly.
Mm.
I'm not really dressed
for that kind of thing.
Okay.
Well...
Now I'm ready.
( laughs )
The future's so bright.
( laughing )
Anyways,
back to the important stuff.
Do you know why most people
screw up their pasta?
- Here we go.
- Not salting the water enough.
You know, it should
taste like the ocean.
You know, when properly
portioned,
salt will not
make food taste salty,
but instead will enhance
the flavors that are
already present.
- ( phone rings )
- It's for me. It's my mom.
She's a partner at a VC firm
so she has her own messaging
service.
- ( clicks on )
- Mom?
Joanie, I got your voicemail.
What's going on?
You made it sound
like World War III
from your message.
Yeah, Dad won't let me
go to the party,
which is bullshit
because you explicitly
told me I could go.
I'm sure he has good
reasons, Bug.
There is no good reason
why I should be stuck here
making pasta from scratch
with freaking Chef Boyardee
and some random lady.
Is it that Michelle woman?
Bingo-rama.
She works for Dad.
Look, when you're at Dad's
house, his word goes.
You know the rules.
- Can you just talk to him?
- No, I don't have time--
Dad! Mom wants to talk to you.
So, what grade are you in?
You know, I'm gonna, like,
go in a second.
You don't have to
talk to me anymore.
Donna, I don't wanna
have this conversation
right now.
- Neither do I.
- She wants to go over
to Jennifer's
and there's not gonna be
any parents there.
I already told her that
she has to listen to you.
She just put you on the phone
because she thought we'd fight
and she'd come out on top.
( laughs )
Since when do you make pasta?
Oh, well, I-I--
I took a cooking class.
Ah.
My parents got divorced
when I was little, too,
so, I know it stinks.
But it gets better.
All right, you're, uh,
you're not going.
So, even with a conservative
estimate of the licensing fees
for the voice-recognition
component,
we'll be in three million
domestic refrigerator-freezers
by the end of Q3.
And I'll hit profitability
by Q4.
So, what is it you do?
- I think this is
definitely him.
- I think it's him!
Listen, man,
we hereby confer
upon you--
Uh, Bob.
( together )
Bob!
...the greatest honor
of Comdex '90:
the Party Pitch Swami
and a Vanquisher
of Earthly Tedium.
And we proudly
present to you...
This...
100% synthetic
ergonomically designed
OSHA-approved
Cisco wrist rest.
Live the life
of your words, Bob.
"Velouria" playing
in background
♪ On to somewhere near ♪
♪ And far in time ♪
♪ Velouria ♪
♪ Her covering ♪
♪ Traveling career ♪
♪ She can really move ♪
♪ Oh, velveteen! ♪ ♪
♪ My Velouria ♪
♪ Even I'll adore ya ♪
♪ Say to me ♪
Hey.
♪ Where have you been? ♪
You want a refill?
Yeah!
Jesus, my refills
want refills!
( laughs )
♪ And how does
lemur's skin ♪
♪ Reflect the sea? ♪
♪ Move away in the shine
of the other ♪
♪ Move away in the tides
of the summer ♪
♪ Every summer, every
My Velouria ♪
I love Space Bike!
Oh! I love you!
( laughing )
Woman:
Cameron?
Cameron!
How are you?
How's Japan?
♪ California ♪
What are you doing here?
- You know, I just...
- ♪ I can see the tears... ♪
came to make an appearance
at the parties, and...
Okay--
Look, I--
I came to see you.
I don't know why
you would do that.
Well, because
I've got this--
There's this thing.
It's really exciting
and I want to show it to you.
- You've got to be kidding.
- Please, just--
Come on, have lunch
with me tomorrow.
No, I'm on an early
flight out to Tokyo.
It's been four years,
we need to--
We don't need
to do anything!
We both did things
we're not proud of,
and if we could turn back
the clock, I'm sure
we'd do it differently.
I can't believe
this is happening.
What, you're gonna tell me
that you've completely moved on?
No.
I think about
you and me every day.
And it makes me furious.
So, let's fix it.
I wanna fix it.
I don't.
Everything okay?
Let's go.
♪ Oh, hey ♪
♪ Velouria ♪
Parmigiano-Reggiano?
Yes, please.
I'm a vegetarian.
Oh, yeah?
Since when?
Since I started
paying attention
to the thinking,
feeling creatures
we share the planet with,
and realized they probably
don't like being eaten.
That's since when.
Well,
you can rinse yours off.
Mmm.
Too late.
It's tainted.
Mmm. This is really good.
Mm.
Grazie.
What did you put in this?
Ah, it's the Bolognese.
It's taken a while
to perfect, but--
( sighs )
Did you know
that almost
all beef you buy
at the supermarket
tests positive
for E. coli?
- Mm-mm.
- Because cows,
when they're slaughtered,
are decapitated.
And when you
decapitate a cow,
all the stuff
in the intestines
and the stomach
flies out through
the neck hole,
all over the body.
And E. coli is found
only in excrement.
Basically...
there's shit
in your Bolognese.
Okay, Joanie,
we are trying to eat.
So am I.
And that's why
we all need to think about
the gross, and, like,
inhumane process
that we get all the stuff
we consume on our plates.
Well, did you know
there's a detectable level
of cow piss in most milk?
( chuckles )
You know, I understand.
When I was five,
I gave up eggs
for a whole year
because I thought
when you cracked the eggs,
that you were killing
little baby chicks,
and every time my dad
made an omelet I would
just burst into tears
- and just cry for hours.
- ( laughs )
I'm 14, not five.
She'll grow out of it.
It's a phase.
You think this
is just a phase?
Okay, Joanie,
why don't you take your plate
into the other room
and we'll talk
about this tomorrow.
Fine.
I am so sorry.
No. No, no, no.
Why? I mean,
I honestly
can barely taste
the shit
in your spaghetti.
Uh, for me,
friendship is...
is very important.
I mean, I...
It's not all
bits and bytes for me.
( laughs )
And I see a lot of movies
and it would just be nice
to have someone special
to share that with
or talk to about that stuff.
Intimacy, that's--
it's-- that's nice.
So, listen, um.
I-- I really am sorry.
I, um--
- I'll see you
at the office.
- Okay.
"Twist Barbie"
playing in background
♪ Ooo, aah, aah ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang,
Twist Barbie ♪
♪ Bang-- ♪
Joanie.
What the hell was that?
You should have just
let me go the party.
Joanie,
just because you are
unhappy does not mean
that you can inflict
your total misery
onto everyone else.
- You're so obvious!
- What is that supposed to mean?
You work for Mom
and now Michelle
works for you.
You could do better.
You already did once.
Can you believe her?
It's like she ambushed me.
Why does she care so much
about kissing and making up?
We don't even
live in the same
country anymore.
She called me.
A few days ago.
Why?
She wanted me to find you...
and bring you some idea.
That's why you're here?
No.
I told her if she
wanted to talk to you,
she could do it herself.
I don't even know
what the idea was.
I didn't read it
and I don't care.
Come on, Cam.
You can trust me.
( wrapper crackling )
( cork pops )
God, that's terrible.
Hey, I think
I figured it out.
You can't beat me.
It's--
It's a system.
You have to count
in Nim sums.
It's just a trick.
Why...
are you here?
You know why.
Nope.
Tell me.
You.
I came to see you.
We shouldn't be up here.
It's getting late.
I have to leave
early tomorrow.
Maybe we should
call it a night.
Yeah.
Yeah, we should
call it a night.
( heavy breathing )
( sharp moan )
Boy on television:
...lawyer.
Girl on television:
Slater, I am impressed.
Spare me.
I want to have
at least seven kids!
Oh, great, so I'll have
to take a number to get
into the bathroom!
Seven kids?
Slater, I don't know.
Consistency.
I can admire that.
Slater: Why?
Because I'm a good boss.
God, I hate it when
Slater does that
stupid turnaround thing
with his chair.
I know.
It's like, okay, we get it,
you're the cool jock.
( indistinct dialogue
continues )
Are you serious?
What?
- You--
- I can't totally commit
to a label.
People aren't one thing.
Yeah.
You're right.
( sighs )
All right.
Is it bad
this morning?
No, it's fine.
I'm just
a little stiff.
Nothing a hot shower
won't fix.
This is ridiculous.
I'm making you switch
bedrooms with me.
Climbing these stairs
is totally dumbass.
Yeah. I'm sure that would
work out great for you.
Nice fancy bed,
big closet...
Oh, it's really
the bathroom I'm after.
Working with you was...
the most fun
I ever had in my life.
Okay?
Oh, Cam.
I picked up the phone
so many times.
Never actually called,
though. Did you?
Well...
I'm here now.
Uh-huh.
Did you even read it?
What?
What I sent Joe.
The idea.
He never even
showed it to me.
What was it?
"Cold Light" playing
♪ Put your heart
in the hands of the city ♪
♪ Working hard
when you're not around ♪
♪ Go home ♪
♪ Baby,
it'll be all right ♪
♪ Put your life
into the cold light ♪
into the cold light. ♪