Chairs.
( electricity crackles )
( footsteps approach )
( sighs )
( door creaks )
( footsteps )
( thudding, creaking )
Hello?
- Hey.
- Hi!
Am I early?
I thought we said 9:00.
Uh, no, yeah.
Yeah, 9:00.
She here yet?
Uh, I know
her plane landed,
so... as long
as she's on it.
( chuckles )
The drive okay?
Yeah, yeah.
It's the weekend,
plus the holiday, so...
- Oh, right.
- Yeah, there was no traffic.
- What's M-NET?
- Oh, uh...
Mutiny's last-ditch
rebranding effort.
Tried to stop the bleeding,
but, you know, still--
Bled.
Anyway, my VC firm
held onto the lease
just in case we needed
a raw space for some
tadpole investment.
( squeaking )
It's pretty raw.
Yeah, well,
the building
was in shambles
when we moved in
four years ago.
I'm sure last year's
quake didn't help.
Oh, God, that was crazy.
What?
- The earthquake.
- Oh, yeah.
- Where were you?
- Work.
- How about you?
( chuckles )
How come you wanted
to meet here?
Oh, I didn't.
Cameron did.
Who knows?
Maybe...
she wanted
to see it again.
Mm-hmm.
By the way, I--
I didn't mean to invite Gordon
without talking to you.
- No, no, it's fine.
- But I--
I just read the paper
and I thought it was
something phenomenal,
and he's still running
the regional network we built,
so it was a no-brainer.
Makes perfect sense.
I'm so sorry about that.
No, really, it's fine.
I'm glad he's coming.
No, I-- the divorce.
Oh. Right.
( stammering )
That the two of you...
- Yeah.
- ...got a divorce.
Anyway...
- I really appreciate it.
- It's no problem.
I mean, it's just
a couple of days
for us to see
if there's even
a "there" there.
Yeah, of course.
( chuckles )
But... I'm excited.
I'm excited, too.
I'm really excited.
I--
Hey, sorry I'm late.
Is Cameron here?
Hey!
How long has it been?
What was that, April?
Yeah, it was actually
two Aprils ago.
- Oh, jeez,
it's been that long?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Well, you look good.
- So do you.
No, I mean it, you look--
you look good.
Thank you.
Hey, can I, uh...
( whispering )
Can you give us a sec?
Oh, of course.
Absolutely. Ahem.
Take all the time you...
- Gordon: Um, can I...?
- Donna: Yeah.
What's up?
Hey, uh, you're okay
that I'm here, right?
I just thought it was
an interesting concept,
given everything
that I've been working on.
And, you know, I haven't
seen Cameron in years.
But look, I don't--
this is your thing, okay?
I don't want to get in the way.
I don't want to interfere.
Gordon, it's fine.
I'm glad you're here.
Him? I'm not so sure.
Gordon:
Yeah, I don't know.
Part of the reason
we've been losing touch is...
Well, you should have
seen him the last time I did.
( sighs )
Hey, Joe.
Glad you're here.
( sighs )
( theme music playing )
Okay,
let's just hold off
for a second
on trying to talk about
what the World Wide Web is
and let's focus
on what it could do.
Okay, so,
here's some context.
Let's say these
are the big boys,
the walled gardens
we're all familiar with.
You've got your Prodigy,
CompuServe, your
America Online--
America Online.
What kind of name
is that, anyways?
It sounds like
a Neil Diamond song.
♪ We're coming
to America... Online! ♪
♪ We're com-- ♪
Okay, and then
we've got NSFNET.
Now, what Berners-Lee
is proposing in this paper
is an application
that could run on this
network of networks.
And now, well,
NSFNET isn't for
commercial use yet,
and it isn't, you know,
sexy at all--
Hey, hey, come on.
NSFNET's dripping with sex.
The size and scope of that
would be formidable.
Still, it's completely separate
from the walled gardens,
where all the real money is.
Right now,
unifying all these networks
is essentially impossible.
There's different software,
different protocols,
different operating system
on different hardware.
But if something like
the World Wide Web expands,
what it ultimately
could do...
is this, right?
Well, no, not really.
No.
Sorry, I know I wasn't
exactly invited.
May I?
Thanks.
Okay, uh...
if I'm understanding this
correctly,
an implementation
would somehow
take these massive
online networks
and do this.
No, no,
you've got it
backwards.
Can you give me the thing?
Good.
Oh.
It's this, isn't it?
Remember,
the World Wide Web
and NSFNET,
or the Internet,
or whatever you want
to call it,
are two different things.
The Web runs on top
of the Internet.
It unifies everything.
It makes it one network.
And that's the incredible
potential behind something
like this.
Right now the online world
is the Tower of Babel.
This is the Rosetta Stone.
And it's running on
state-of-the-art NeXT
hardware and software.
( stammering )
That's my biggest problem.
NeXTSTEP is not a problem;
it's perfect.
Okay, yeah, but I run
a network that's not
just on a whiteboard.
All right,
here we go.
The NeXT is
a state-of-the-art system.
Designed by a disgraced
megalomaniac who loves
form over function.
No wonder you love the NeXT.
Look, if we're talking
about a network
that lives exclusively
on a ridiculously overpriced
machine
that doesn't really play nice
with anything else in the
technological landscape,
what we're really
looking at...
Oh. Well, please...
- Is this.
- ...be my guest.
A tiny little
desert island
that nobody
gives a shit about.
( chuckles )
Cameron?
What do you think?
Okay.
Um...
say we're all talking
the same way.
Cool.
What are we saying?
Are we just
shooting the breeze?
Are we playing games?
Are we looking
to get laid?
- Are we just
mindlessly shopping?
- That's an excellent point.
Content is paramount,
but this box is
the equivalent
of a 500,000-seat
state-of-the-art stadium,
and we build that,
we own that, we win.
But what's the point
of having a giant stadium
if you don't
have a kickass band
to play the venue?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, guys,
the last thing that we need
to do right now
is hop in the car and
race out to the parking lot
of an empty stadium
before rock and roll
is even invented.
Hey, guys,
we are early.
And I'm not talking,
"Let's all just run down
to the IHOP
and grab
some silver dollar
pancakes" early.
We are years and years
early on this.
Trust me, okay?
This is what I do.
- I can't believe
you don't see this.
- Look, I agree.
Okay, the World Wide Web
could be the next best thing
since sliced bread.
But right now, it's a tiny
little academic petri dish
- running on a NeXT computer.
- In Europe.
- Yes, is Europe.
- Then what exactly
are we all doing here?
Okay, hold on, hold on.
Just-- let's not lose
the shared idea here.
There's a shared protocol.
This is a universal language.
- So it's Esperanto.
- What the heck is Esperanto?
It's a language for idiots
that failed.
Okay, you know what?
Let's-- why don't we
take a break for lunch?
It's, like, 10:30.
I mean, I could eat.
Sure.
( footsteps approaching )
Gordon went out
to get some pizza.
I figured maybe
it'd been a while since
you had that in Japan.
There's a Domino's
around the corner
from our apartment.
Oh.
Look, you came all this way.
It just seems like
you don't want to be here.
I said I'd listen.
Donna, it's not like
this is the only thing
we're doing stateside.
I have a meeting with Atari.
Tom has to meet with SEGA U.S.--
And you're doing Christmas
in Texas with his family,
I know.
Cam, we planned
this whole thing
around your travel.
In Vegas you said
this was a good idea.
It is a good idea.
But is also has severe
limitations in reality.
It's good
to see you, Joe.
Thanks.
It's good to see you
doing so well.
- As opposed to...?
- No, it's just--
Cameron said--
she said at COMDEX
you were--
you were having a bit
of a rough go of it,
that's all.
I'm sorry to hear
about what happened.
I never met Ryan,
but Cameron spoke
really highly of him.
It was difficult.
For a long time.
But I'm doing
so much better
since I've reconnected
with your wife.
- Donna: Hold on--
- ( groans )
I feel like we're
talking in circles.
What we're
really looking at is...
Ow!
You know, I'd like to
take things in a different
direction, if I could.
I'd like to talk about
what I learned in Paris.
Paris?
The whimsical art
of mime?
I went to the Hypertext
Conference a few weeks ago.
- The what conference?
- Hypertext.
Some pretty big names
were there-- Apple, Xerox.
- I'm surprised you
didn't hear about it.
- Yeah, me, too.
It was right after
I saw you in COMDEX.
Okay, so,
Hypertext Conference.
Berners-Lee was there
and he was talking to
anyone who would listen.
He handed out
the entire Web toolkit,
the transfer protocol,
the mark-up language,
the server software,
everything.
- Wait, you met him?
- You have all of that?
- Yeah.
- That would have been useful
to know this morning, maybe.
What's so interesting
about a programming language
like Hypertext--
It's not a programming language,
it's just a text that accesses
other texts.
Yes,
I'm actually talking about
HTML, the mark-up language.
What's so interesting
about it is its simplicity.
With a very basic
set of rules,
you can create pages
of information, objects,
and eventually media
when the bandwidth increases.
So, I cornered
the guys at CERN.
Sorry, what is CERN?
CERN.
European Organization
for Nuclear Research.
Oh, right, nuclear research.
Okay, I see the connection.
Sorry, I'm not hearing
the "C" word in it.
Nobody was paying
any attention to them.
In a way, they reminded me
of Gordon and Donna,
COMDEX '81.
- Oh, yeah.
- What, pathetic?
Devastatingly handsome?
Geniuses ahead of their time.
Berners-Lee handed out
guidebooks not only for HTML,
but HTTP,
the transfer protocol,
the call-and-response process
for moving information like this
across to potential networks.
Addressing protocol
is TCP/IP.
But HTTP is the abstraction
application layer protocol
that sits on top of TCP/IP
symbiotically, right, Tom?
With HTTP,
any machine can
become a client,
any machine
can become a server,
easily exchanging files.
No, files are FTP,
as in File Transfer
Protocol.
It's the one that has
"file" in the name of it.
What I am saying is
HTTP will eventually
supplant FTP.
What I'm saying is
it can do it all.
That's interesting.
Really? FTP?
That's interesting?
I'd like to get back
to an important point--
simplicity.
Both HTML and HTTP
are breathtakingly simple.
And this kind of elegance
allows for versatility,
it allows for universality--
Yes, a universal language,
like I said.
And the best part is,
the online catalogue viewer,
the transfer protocol,
the Web server software,
all of it is free.
I have a problem
with open source.
- You do?
- Yeah, I do.
Do you know how many
bad video game pitches
I sit through
every single day?
The only way SEGA stays SEGA,
or Nintendo stays Nintendo,
is by not turning
those pitches into products.
- That's not--
- No, no.
Because open source
allows the lunatics
to run the asylum.
And every time--
every time--
you put well-made code
out into the world,
for people
to screw around with,
it causes major problems.
I mean,
just look what happened
to MacMillan Utility.
- What are you doing?
- What?
What happened
to MacMillan Utility?
Um, gee.
The release of their
source code online
vaporized millions
of shareholder dollars.
- And, long story short,
you're not around anymore.
- Okay!
- Or you could look at it
a different way.
- Uh-huh.
That with everyone
creating something
like the Web together,
some potentially amazing
things could happen.
One, it gets built
very fast.
Two, it becomes
huge in size.
Three, it's constantly
being edited and refined,
so it's improving
at a massive rate.
And four,
there's no overlord
controlling things.
Gordon:
And what network
is this giant, miraculous
nebula of collaboration
happening on?
You know as well as I do
that something like this could
change the face of the Internet.
The Internet
is not available
for commercial use.
Do you know how much money
I poured into lobbying, trying
to get deregulation through?
Look, everybody wants this
and it's gonna happen
eventually.
But we are early,
and it's all about timing.
If the timing's off, we're dead.
Timing's what killed Mutiny.
- Timing didn't kill Mutiny.
- I'm sorry...
The right people
make it the right time.
We can move this forward.
We can be the people
that make that future happen.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
I'm so sick of hearing
about the future.
What is that?
The future is just another
crappy version of the present.
It's some bribe
people offer you
to make you do what they want
instead of what you want.
This future
can be different.
( laughs )
Oh, Jesus, that should be
on your business card, Joe.
How many times
are you people
gonna fall for this?
You know,
I'm with Joe.
I can't believe
I'm saying that,
but I'm with Joe.
Of course you're with Joe.
You guys are the money people.
But it's me and Cameron
that actually have to do it.
- Look, nobody's doing
anything yet--
- Exactly.
( knocks on table )
Yeah, uh, guys,
it's been fun,
but I think we're
gonna hit the road.
Yeah, it's been,
uh, thorough.
Yeah, okay, we can call it
a day and reconvene
in the morning.
Well,
you know, maybe--
maybe tomorrow
will go better.
There's not gonna
be a tomorrow.
Hey, Cameron?
Come back tomorrow.
You flew halfway
across the world.
Donna's trying.
Just give her a chance.
Joe...
We got to see if there's
something here.
This is a mess, Joe.
It's just a mess.
( engine starts )
"All My Ex's Live in Texas"
playing in background
♪ All my exes
live in Texas... ♪
( vocalizing )
♪ Live in Texas ♪
♪ ...the place
I'd dearly love to be... ♪
Come on, now.
♪ But all my exes
live in Texas ♪
♪ And that's why
I hang my hat...♪
Permission
to come aboard?
Permission granted.
( turns off radio )
- Careful there
with them city shoes.
- Oh, sorry.
Might wanna wait a sec
till you get your sea legs
under you.
That's all right.
Huh.
Cool boat.
Hard to sail
in a driveway,
though.
Yup.
Well, I was beating
that slot
up between Angel Island
and Golden Gate last month,
and I didn't
heel fast enough
in the shallows
and I scratched the shit
out of my gelcoat.
( laughs )
Well, look at you!
The salty sailor.
Look at you.
Yeah, I know.
Just all grown up, right?
Well, hell, Cameron,
you were all grown up
before I ever met you.
- Beer?
- Yeah.
How'd it go this morning
with Donna?
How did you...?
Oh, Diane told me.
Whose driveway you
think you're in?
( can pops )
How is Diane?
She's good.
Good.
- Yeah? You guys
are still--
- Yup.
She still goes to work
and I stay retired.
Some weekends we sail
up to Sausalito or Tiburon.
Mostly go to the vineyard
if we got a couple
of extra days.
So Californian.
You take her to Texas yet?
I have, yeah.
Loved the rodeo.
Hated everything else.
- ( laughs )
- And I think she was just
being polite about the rodeo.
So, what's next?
Wedding bells?
Oh, sure, we've talked
about it, but, no.
Hell, between us
we got three kids
aged 35 to 14,
and that's enough.
Hey,
how's old Tommy Rendon?
- Uh--
- Kids on the radar
for you yet?
Ooh, no.
No, I--
Tom wants them, but...
No. If it was up to me,
we'd just get them
out of a vending machine
like everything else
in Japan.
- Like what?
- Uh... edible underwear.
- Come on!
- Yeah.
Plus, you know,
we're just so far
from home these days.
Although, what the hell
is home anymore?
Well, you're here now,
ain't ya?
Yeah, I'm here.
It only took me 24 hours
to realize that coming back
was a mistake.
Well, Donna says
it's a pretty hot idea.
Had to be
to get all you yokels
in the same room again.
It is.
It's just...
too many cooks.
Fool me twice, right?
Was that what happened?
You got fooled?
And also I just have
my own thing going on
that I'm busy with, so...
Yeah. Space Bike.
Yeah.
That's right, I got it.
I tried it out.
- Really?
- Well, look--
well,
it's not for me.
I am just amazed
that you even installed it.
I couldn't make
heads or tails of it,
to tell you the truth.
Well,
who's that little bastard
with the chainsaw?
Who's that one?
And then you got
the force field thing.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hell, it's like
you can't even win.
Nope.
No, you can't.
( knocking )
( stammering )
Sorry, I'm just here
for Haley's retainer.
She conveniently
forgot it again.
Yeah, I think
I saw it upstairs.
Oh, did you
want me to--
'cause I can go--
No, no, I can get it.
Come on in.
You know, I, uh...
still sleep up there
every night.
Hey, why don't
you get yourself
a glass of wine?
- Uh...
- You look like
you could use one.
You know where it is.
( jazz music playing )
The key to the bisque
is the Parmesan toast.
Four years ago,
the only Parmesan
you knew about was powdered.
Yeah, well,
I still got that, too.
Joanie eats it
by the spoonful.
Dirty little secret?
Teenage girls
are just as disgusting
as teenage boys.
Well, have you seen
this thing that she does
with the chocolate syrup?
And the milk?
It's atrocious.
- Oh, my God.
- Ugh.
Yeah,
speaking of cheese,
seems like Joe MacMillan
is back in rare form.
Yes, you've gone
and woken up the beast.
Well, it was my only way
to get to Cameron.
It was a long shot
and it didn't even work.
I had to go myself.
I don't know, maybe that
didn't even work either.
Yeah, well, what were you
gonna do all these years,
you know?
Between work
and the kids?
You know, get on a plane
and fly to Tokyo?
Well, I could pitch
a terrible video game
to Tom.
No, no, no.
You would never get
a meeting with someone
as important as Tom.
( both laughing )
- You know, if they do
come back tomorrow...
- Yeah?
I got this really
great idea for them.
- Yeah, what's that?
- For a video game.
Basically,
it's this conveyor belt
filled with
all these light bulbs,
but you have to shit on them
before they turn on.
Wait, I have
the perfect title.
- Mm-hmm.
- Ready?
"You're an Asshole."
Listen, I--
I apologize today
for calling you
a money person.
- Oh.
- I didn't mean it.
It just kind of
came out.
Oh. It's true, though.
These days.
I don't know,
maybe it was a mistake--
bringing everybody
back together and trying
to fix things.
Yeah, well,
if nobody shows up tomorrow,
I'm still interested.
Really?
It didn't seem
like that today.
What the--
all I said was,
you're early.
Okay, it's a disservice
to everyone if I didn't
say that.
You know, and look,
I've--
I've been wrong before.
I'll be the first
to admit that.
Can I ask you
a weird question?
Yeah, shoot.
Are you having just
a ton of sex these days?
Um...
I do all right.
How about you?
Yeah. Same.
Huh.
Uh, are you--
are you seeing anyone
right now?
Nope.
Good. 'Cause there's
something really weird
I want to ask you.
Would you be open to...
meeting someone?
Like, for a date?
I think you and this guy
would really hit it off.
What?
Yeah, there's this
really great guy I know.
He runs the computer lab
programs at Cal.
He's really nice
and I just thought,
you're free, he's free...
I don't know.
( keyboard clicking )
What are you doing?
I'm trying to finish
this presentation.
My battery died,
so I'm using yours.
Is that okay?
Yeah, it's fine.
How's Bos?
Yeah, he's good.
Oh, look...
I know today
wasn't fun for you,
so if you don't want
to come back tomorrow,
you don't have to.
- So, you're going?
- Well...
- Yeah, I guess so.
- Okay, well, I guess
I'm going, too.
Good.
Let me get in the shower.
( door closes )
( shower running )
( marker squeaking )
What's up with him?
He says he needs
five minutes.
Huh.
Wow. Man, did I wake up
with a headache
this morning.
Hey, you left
kind of fast last night.
I hope I didn't
say anything dumb.
You know,
about the date.
Gordon, it's fine.
Oh, great.
I mean, you know, good.
I'd love his number.
Unless, you know--
if it would be weird...
No.
No, I mean...
Yeah, no problem.
( door slams )
Oh, you're here.
( laughs )
You're all here.
Let's get started.
Berners-Lee wrote HTML
to view and edit the Web,
HTTP so that it
could talk to itself.
The chatter
could be cacophonous.
It could be
deafeningly silent.
Big picture--
what will the World
Wide Web become?
Short answer--
who knows?
Okay, so,
what's your point?
It's a waste of time
to try to figure out
what the Web will become.
We just don't know.
Because right now,
at the end of the day,
it's just an online
research catalogue
running on
NeXT computers
on a small network
in Europe.
So, you're saying
everything we've
talked about
since we got here
has been a waste of time?
I'm saying,
let's take a step back.
Literally, a step back.
Yeah, but what is this
on the board?
It's the code
for the Web browser.
And you wrote it all
on the whiteboard.
The online catalogue
of research?
Full of Norwegian dudes,
physics papers, and particle
diagrams and stuff?
Yeah, and we care
about this because why?
How did we all
get here today?
The choices we made,
the sheer force of our will,
something like that?
Here's another answer--
the winds of fate.
Random coincidence,
some unseen hand
just pushing us along.
Destiny.
How did we all
get here today?
We walked through
this door.
We don't have to build
a big white box or a stadium,
or invent rock and roll.
The moment we decide
what the Web is,
we've lost.
The moment we try
to tell people what
to do with it,
we've lost.
All we have to do
is build a door
and let them inside.
When I was five,
my mother took me
to the city.
And we went through
the Holland Tunnel,
and it was basic.
Concrete and steel.
But it was also my excitement
sitting in the backseat,
wondering when it was
going to be our turn
to emerge.
It was the explosion
of sunlight.
And when we exited
the tunnel,
all of Manhattan
was laid out before us.
And that was the best part
of the trip--
the amazing possibility
to be able to go anywhere
within something
that is magnificent
and never-ending.
This is the first
Web browser,
the rudimentary one
CERN built to view
and edit research.
I wrote it up here for you
to see how simple it is.
It takes up one whiteboard--
that's basic concrete and steel.
But we can take this
and we can build a door,
and we can be
the first ones to do it.
Because right now,
everyone else sees this as--
As an online
research catalogue.
Running on NeXT.
On a network in Europe.
And with this handful of code,
we can build the Holland Tunnel.
I don't see it.
I don't.
I mean, is it a door,
or is it a tunnel?
Or is it the Tower of Babel?
Or is it a Rosetta Stone,
or is it a stadium?
You can't even decide
on a metaphor.
And if the big idea here
is the browser,
and it's that easy
to build, then it's
not a big idea at all.
It's a foregone
conclusion.
And how can we win
at something when anyone--
anyone, including
Xerox and Apple
and all the actual
players from your little
Hypertext shindig,
can step in
at any moment
and crush us?
It will be
competitive,
because whoever owns the door
can charge admission.
But I sincerely believe
that with the people
in this room,
we have a chance
to build the best--
And what makes you think
you have all the people
in this room, Joe?
Come on, Cam,
let's go.
Come on, Cam.
Let's go.
Let's cut
the bullshit, Tom.
- Your problem isn't the idea.
- You're right, Joe.
Do you know
what my problem is?
I don't want to see
Cameron end up like Ryan.
Tom!
You say his name
one more time--
Ryan.
Do you remember him?
Well, hey, lucky for us,
wives don't get a vote.
You--
- Donna: Oh, my God.
- Tom!
( both panting )
( wood cracking )
( screams )
Joe!
Cameron:
Joe?!
Cameron: Go!
( groans )
( woman speaking over P.A. )
I know.
You're lucky
you're not dead.
Listen, Joe,
if we have any chance
in hell at this,
it's this kind
of personal bullshit
that's going to sink us
before we even start.
- Us?
- Yeah,
Cameron was right.
There's no such thing
as the future, hey?
All there is is now.
Maybe we're not early.
Maybe if we do it now,
we could be the first.
Regardless,
I am done waiting.
I can't let
this one get away.
Then don't.
Hey, he's fine.
He broke his wrist,
but he's okay.
What happened at COMDEX?
What?
Nothing.
Nothing happened.
I need some air.
( sighs )
You okay?
So easy to make Joe
the bad guy.
I mean...
making him the villain
takes the blame away,
but in everything
that's happened with him,
every single time...
I deserve some
of the blame, too.
And it's the same
with you, you know?
Things fell apart.
And you did
what you did,
but a lot of it
was my fault.
This is a really
cool idea.
Yeah,
I think so, too!
And, look,
if Joe is
a problem for you,
then he doesn't
have to be here.
We can get rid of him.
- We all patched in?
- Yeah, give it a try.
Yup, we're in,
good and speedy.
So, this is
your baby, huh?
Yeah, the little
network that could.
The DSP in this cube
is amazing.
Not only are
we getting clean 56K,
we can do this
at the same time.
"King of Wishful Thinking"
playing in background
♪ I'll get over you,
I know... ♪
- Sounds pretty good, huh?
- Yeah, is that coming
off the CD-ROM?
♪ I'll pretend my ship's
not sinking... ♪
- ( music stops )
- We should really focus.
Okay, so through NSFNET,
we can connect to CERN?
Yes, but we're gonna crawl
once we jump to Europe.
Why? The TAT-8
is fiber optic.
Yeah, but it's also buried
along the continental shelf
and constantly being
attacked by sharks.
Apparently, they can sense
the electrical radiation.
- I know.
- I love your mind.
You know,
seven grand a pop
is still insane,
and I don't know
why the cube is magnesium,
but I still appreciate
a good machine.
Yeah, well...
you know what they say,
software comes and goes...
Both:
But hardware is forever.
( Donna chuckles )
Okay. Do you have
everything?
- Yeah.
- Okay, this is good.
This is good.
Yeah, I'll knock out
my meetings today
and get in
a few days early,
I'll see the family,
get my bearings.
I think-- I think
it will help me
recalibrate.
Yeah, this is good.
Yeah,
and I'll pick you up
at the airport
day after tomorrow,
okay?
- I'll be there.
- Okay.
Wait, um...
I'm really sorry
that I didn't trust you.
I don't like
who I've been
this weekend.
It's been a weird
situation for me, too.
The other night
at the hotel,
I was reading your emails
on your laptop.
I can't believe
that I did that.
I just couldn't get
Joe out of my head,
and it was completely
irrational and I'm sorry.
I just-- don't want us
to lie to one another.
Because I love you.
I love you, too.
( sighs )
- Okay.
Joe...
Joe, I am...
Joe, I-- I just wanted
to apologize again
for yesterday.
The way I behaved...
I was way, way,
way out of line.
I was out of line, too.
Sorry.
- I love you.
- Love you.
- I'll see you.
- Okay.
( engine starts )
Hey, they're ready
downstairs.
Donna...
I can't work
with you.
What?
I can't work with you.
It will never
be like it was.
It can't be.
But last night,
we-- we talked.
It was good.
I don't understand.
You know
why I wanted us
to meet here?
I just didn't want
to forget what had happened,
how painful that was.
Why?
And then I almost
did forget last night
when we talked,
when it felt good,
when I was with
my friend again.
And then
you reminded me
how easily you toss
people aside
when you feel like
they're in your way.
This about Joe.
No, this is about you.
Jesus!
I was trying
to help you.
All I was ever trying
to do was help you.
Well...
the thing is,
Donna,
I love this project...
and I want to work on it.
Take it.
( breathing deeply )
- ( engine starts )
- Damn it.
- ( engine shuts off )
- ( crying )
( sobbing )
( touch tones beeping )
It's me.
I'm headed to the office.
I need a flight
to Switzerland
and I need to meet
with CERN when I get there.
( engine starts )
( keyboard clicking )
Where the hell
is Cameron?
You know how long
I've been waiting,
just sitting around
the last four years,
twiddling my thumbs?
Maybe this futures bet we made
will finally pay off.
I'm in love with her.
( footsteps approach )
Where's Donna?
She left.
"New Morning" playing
All right.
Let's do this.
♪ Can't you hear
that rooster crowing ♪
♪ Rabbit running down
across the road ♪
♪ Underneath
the bridge ♪
♪ Where the water
flowed through? ♪
♪ So happy just
to see you smile ♪
♪ Underneath
that sky of blue ♪
♪ On this new morning ♪
♪ New morning ♪
♪ With you. ♪
( theme music playing )