♪♪
[Telephone ringing]
Happy New Year.
How's Tokyo?
Cameron: Good.
Cold.
Good. Good.
Well, uh...
Is that her?
We got some first steps
for the browser
that we want to walk you through
so we can, uh, you know,
hit the ground running
when you get back to town.
Gordon, I'm gonna be working
on this project remotely.
I-I need to talk
to Joe.
Just me.
Yeah. Okay.
Wants to talk to you.
Hello?
How you doing?
♪♪
I don't understand.
I told Tom
what happened.
And he and I, uh,
we both agreed
that it would be best
if I worked
on the browser remotely --
from here.
♪♪
[Keypad beeping musically]
What time is it there?
They're 17 hours ahead,
so whatever time
it is here...
[Hammering]
Look, she doesn't need
to be on the phone
for us to upload it
to Gopher.
She wrote it.
She needs to be available.
Guys, I need --
I need --
Stop hammering!
Please!
You know
it's midnight there.
This is the time
she specified.
Maybe Godzilla's
fighting Mothra again.
We're gonna try her again
in 20 minutes.
[Saw whirring]
Guys!
Guys, guys, please!
All right?
It's too early in the morning
for this.
♪♪
That is because nobody
is downloading it at all.
No, you're right.
Forgive me.
69 downloads last quarter.
Is that better?
[Chuckles]
A year and we are barely
a ripple in the pond.
Of course it has to do
with the bugs.
I'm tracking them
as fast as I can,
but you take
forever to --
Okay.
Okay, fine.
That would be fine.
-How's Cameron?
-Never available.
Or if we do somehow
manage to get her on the phone,
she's busy
or defensive or --
Stuck at 69 downloads.
Look, Joe,
we're building
the core ISP business
upstairs by the day,
which means we don't need
overnight success
with the web browser.
But why do you keep
putting yourself
through this with her?
This work is important.
That's not what I asked.
I'll make sure those bugs
get fixed.
♪♪
[Clears throat]
[Telephone ringing]
[Indistinct conversations]
Shep, have you talked
to Cameron?
Uh, Gordon,
this is Mike Houseman
from America Online.
-Great to meet you, Gordon.
-Yeah, likewise.
Yeah, I want to talk
about acquiring your user base.
Is AOL really that afraid
of the open Internet?
[Chuckles]
Well, it's either that
or we crush you
when we expand west.
Ah, well, let me tell you
something, Mike --
I need to show you
something right now.
Mike, this is Joe MacMillan.
He's our Web Services division.
Impressive.
You're into the Web.
It's where
everything's headed.
Gordon.
Excuse us.
It's called Mosaic.
All right, so there's
another browser in the game.
We still got Nexus,
Viola, Midas --
Don't forget Millennium,
thanks to Donna.
Who's got just as much of
a right to this idea as we do.
But those aren't this.
Inline images,
Web forums support,
available
on every platform.
If Cameron hadn't been
radio silent for five months,
if she had fixed the bugs,
helped us iterate...
I don't mind losing,
but we're not even gonna
get a chance to compete.
Where the hell
is Cameron?
♪♪
Now we do our own chip.
[Pages rustling]
Over here.
You all right?
Yeah.
Fine.
I bet it was
her new game.
I'm sure
she just got wrapped up in it,
forgot all about us.
What if we uncapped usage?
You know, unlimited access
for every customer --
you know,
no more hourly rates,
just a, you know,
flat monthly fee?
That's a good idea,
smart.
Look, I don't mean
to harp on it,
but what galls me
is that she still owes us
a final version.
We had
a first-mover advantage.
Now Mosaic is the front door
to the Web.
Mm.
Yeah, I heard they had
a million downloads
in the first six months.
Those numbers
have to be inflated.
Meanwhile, Loadstar stands
at a whopping 431.
Well, maybe that's okay.
But we can build
a Mosaic-killer.
She couldn't do it.
We'll find
someone who can.
Joe, how many times
do you have to be right?
Maybe we should just be
grateful or something.
I mean,
this is technology
that we could only have dreamed
of back in that garage.
[Sighs]
You should've
brought Ozzie.
I wouldn't have minded.
Yeah.
What?
[Chuckling] Nothing.
We broke up
three weeks ago.
Oh, man.
Hey, Gordon...
happy 40th.
Cheers.
♪♪
[Keyboard clacking]
Try the corridor again.
We were just there,
and all we found
was this rusty
walking-stick thing.
Can you equip it?
"The stick particulates
in your hand"?
Cool.
Dude, what?
[Sighs]
This feels like homework.
Seriously, I'm getting cold
just watching this.
Oh, good --
another puzzle.
Good thing we haven't seen
anybody in like 10 minutes.
You can't even
kill anything.
Ah, shoot.
[Keyboard clacks]
Ah.
Okay.
[Musical chimes]
Wait. What the hell?
We're back at the beginning?
This is bullshit.
Who are you?
Hi.
What's your favorite
video game right now?
-Mortal Kombat.
-Yeah, Mortal Kombat.
I prefer Street Fighter II
for the superior controls
and graphics.
Okay.
Thank you, guys, for coming in.
Here's your Pioneer Chicken
gift certificates.
We appreciate
your feedback.
Guys, this is not
our target demographic.
We need to be going
after higher GPAs,
readers with immersive fantasy
and sci-fi interests.
This isn't a game you play.
It's a game you live.
How many websites now?
561.
And I found a new one
for you.
Look, if this is the one
that translates your name
into Hawaiian,
I already did it.
And?
Kolekona.
Hey, look at this one.
It's a, uh --
It's a coffee pot.
That is a coffee pot
at he University of Cambridge,
5,000 miles away.
That's not a picture.
That's a live video feed.
Well, it looks
really alive.
It's...fascinating.
Listen.
Joe, I actually came
down here
to chat with you
about something.
Shoot.
Well, I was wondering if
you'd consider moving upstairs.
Why?
Well,
the Web Services division
hasn't originally grown
the way we thought it would,
and, you know, we could
really use the server space.
And -- And now that
the browser's dead --
Dead? We might have stalled
a little bit,
but that's because
we're just getting started.
[Chuckles]
I'm not moving upstairs.
If anything,
you're moving down here.
Listen, Joe,
you've been down here
for almost three years,
and it's still just you,
an ergonomic chair,
and 500 Post-its.
Listen.
I'll say it again.
You did it.
You and Ryan called it.
You said the Internet would be
the next great public utility.
Well, guess what?
We're here.
We did it.
We are Thomas Edison.
We built
the power company.
So why don't you
come upstairs
and run the power company
with me?
Gordon, nobody remembers
the power company.
Came free in the mail with
my Popular Mechanics this month.
AOL is carpet-bombing.
They're going after
our entire territory.
They're trying to take down
CompuServe and Prodigy,
but we could get caught
in the crossfire.
All I'm saying is,
if we're about to go to war,
it'd be nice to have you
in the fight.
♪♪
[Elevator dings]
[Telephone rings]
♪♪
Jesus.
It has video now.
Mother--
[Whirring]
♪♪
No, Abe, you needed
to fully implement
-the updates this morning
-You try reformatting HTML
with a screaming 6-month-old
in your arm.
Oh, that's just great timing,
isn't it?
-Oh, yeah, it is.
-Yeah. Okay, good.
♪♪
She'll be right with you.
Thank you.
♪♪
Carrot, grapefruit,
little bit of ginger.
Mmm.
Microsoft didn't get
the bump they wanted
from the Home
announcement.
I know.
Two hundredths of a point.
Well, Windows is still
the official O.S.
of the White House.
♪♪
[Sighs]
Good morning.
First off, thanks
for calling us in this morning.
Believe me,
if you hadn't had reached out,
we would've --
You know, we would've been
bothering you to get in here
because we
are just so darn excited
about some of these steps
we're taking to surpass Mosaic.
By the time we are done
fully implementing,
it'll be like, "Mosaic?
What's Mosaic?"
So, just to catch you up,
Millennium now supports...
Right.
Uh, inline images.
Yeah, we got a stop button
right there
to halt web-page loads.
See?
And, uh, we should have
our very own "hotlists" soon.
Video?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
We are hard at work on that.
Matter of days.
We've also been proactive
with our branding efforts --
you know, getting our name
out there.
Greg, the mouse pads,
please.
You know,
to spread the word,
and, um, our download numbers,
while not Mosaic's,
are really starting
to edge out Loadstar, so...
But we don't want to be
just chasing Mosaic, do we?
You guys are too talented
for that.
You need to be pursuing
your own vision,
not aping somebody else's,
right?
We couldn't agree more.
Yes.
[Chuckles]
Wonderful.
Then we are all set.
I was really rooting
for you guys.
Thanks, Donna.
We really appreciate it.
Did we just get
defunded?
♪♪
Ahh.
-Get your hands off me.
-You asked.
I said
don't touch me, Abe!
Jesus!
♪♪
[Drumming]
[Cheers and applause]
♪♪
Oh, oh, oh!
All right!
All right.
[Laughs]
[Cheering]
♪♪
Yeah!
[Cheers and applause]
♪♪
[Cheering]
[Cheers and applause]
Yeah!
♪♪
[Cheers and applause]
Wow.
Look who it is.
I was on the company
invite list.
Mm.
So you do get e-mails.
-Have you seen Mosaic?
-I saw Mosaic.
I haven't heard from you
in five months.
Now you're just here.
Honestly, I didn't even know
you were in the country.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I should've --
You know, I-I thought I was
gonna find time to talk to you.
I didn't know the party
was gonna be so --
Look, look, look.
Don't worry about it.
To be honest with you,
I'm not even that mad.
Joe's gonna kill you.
Is he here?
Joe MacMillan at a party?
You've been out of the loop
for a while.
Bosworth: Well, come on!
[Laughs]
Ah!
Hey, what the heck
are you doing here?
My God! Look!
I'm -- I'm doing some, um,
promotion for my new game.
Yeah, The Pilgrim, sure.
I've seen it.
Ooh, looks spooky.
Ooh.
By the way, John absolutely
loved that sailing compass.
Oh, oh.
Sure. I got it mounted
right on the bulkhead.
You know,
we got to get over there
and see these guys
some time. Soon?
Once Diane figures out how
to make it business write-off.
[Chuckles]
Gee, John, thanks.
I'm kidding.
Oh, I mean, you guys are welcome
whenever you want.
I just saw Joanie,
so I'm gonna go say hi.
Okay.
Good to see you.
Hey, uh...
when are you gonna take me
out on that boat?
Oh, we'll get out there soon,
Cap'n.
I'm gonna go
get cleaned up.
Okay.
You need it.
See you guys
in a little bit.
[Chuckling] Okay.
By the looks of all this,
CalNect pulls down,
what, 50, 60 mil a year?
60.
Well, hell, 75 now
that they're down in Arizona.
Still, 25 ISP competitors
in the landscape and growing,
and CalNect isn't
a member of the C.I.X.
and won't be anytime soon.
Well, yeah.
Gordon's pretty good
at watching his henhouse.
I wouldn't worry.
John, all I'm saying is
that with AOL coming to town,
all of this seems overly
optimistic, don't you think?
[Applause]
♪♪
Cameron?
[Both laugh]
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
-I can't believe you're here!
-Okay.
Oh, my God!
Guys, listen.
This is Cameron.
Like -- like, the Cameron Howe.
-Yes.
-Nice, dude.
-She invented Space Bike.
-Mm-hmm.
What's the other one called?
Pilgrim.
Right.
That is so cool.
Do you wanna play
Mortal Kombat?
Yeah.
[Chuckles]
Oh...no.
You guys go ahead.
♪ That's how we do it
every single day ♪
Haley?
Hi.
Hi!
Um, o hisashiburi desu ne.
Oh. Impressive.
[Laughs]
I've been, you know, practicing
off those CDs you sent.
Yes. Well, gengo o hitotsu
wa kesshite tarinai.
Um...
Anata wa subarashi
ninjindesu.
-[Laughs]
-No?
-No.
-No, what?
You said I was
an awesome carrot.
[Laughs]
Oh.
You don't have to worry.
My mom's not here.
[Indistinct conversations]
-Hey, man.
-Hey.
Good to see ya.
I didn't think
you'd make it.
Glad to know
I can still surprise you.
So, um, no present?
Actually,
I did get you something.
I was kidding.
A whole box of them at the front
counter at Blockbuster.
Jesus.
AOL's everywhere now.
I'm, uh --
I'm in this fight with you.
But I want Shep's office.
It gets the most sunlight.
Done.
Um...
Cameron's here.
Okay, so I've got http//cad.ucla
/edu/repository/bonsai/html.
Yep.
That's it.
You're a fellow bonsai
enthusiast, I take it?
No.
But I'm gonna check out
your website.
Okay.
[Indistinct conversations]
I heard you didn't come
to parties anymore.
It's Gordon's birthday.
How's Tom?
Tom is good.
He, um...
He just got promoted
to head of development
at Sega, so...
That's great.
You're mad at me.
["Happy Birthday" playing]
♪ Happy birthday,
happy birthday ♪
Wouldn't you be?
♪ Happy birthday,
happy birthday ♪
Yeah.
[Cheering]
♪ Happy, happy birthday
in a hot bath ♪
♪ To those nice, nice nights ♪
♪ I remember always, always
I got such a fright ♪
♪ Seeing them
in my dark cupboard ♪
I got to go.
♪ With my great big cake ♪
♪ If they were,
if they were me ♪
Thank you all for coming!
[Cheering]
["Doll Parts" playing]
♪ I am ♪
Can I have a whiskey?
♪ Doll eyes ♪
♪ Doll mouth ♪
♪ Doll legs ♪
♪ I am ♪
♪ Doll arms ♪
♪ Big veins ♪
♪ Dog bait ♪
♪ Yeah, they really want you ♪
♪ They really want you ♪
♪ They really do ♪
♪ Yeah, they really want you ♪
♪ They really want you ♪
♪ And I do, too ♪
♪ I want to be the girl
with the most cake ♪
♪ He only loves those things ♪
♪ Because he loves
to see them break ♪
♪ I fake it so real,
I am beyond fake ♪
♪ And someday,
you will ache like I ache ♪
Am I cruel?
Of course not.
♪ Someday,
you will ache like I ache ♪
Why would you ask that?
♪ And someday,
you will ache like I ache ♪
All right.
♪ And someday,
you will ache like I ache ♪
♪ Someday,
[Video game music playing]
[Groans]
What time is it?
Crack of noon.
Rise and shine.
Oh, God.
You're a monster.
Pete can give you a ride home
if you need one.
Who's Pete?
My driver.
You'll love him.
He used to be
a city tax planner
and loves books on tape.
[Sighs]
Is it dark in the car?
Can I sleep in there
with the A.C. on?
Of course.
As long as you're all right
with the dulcet tones
of Robert Ludlum
thrillers.
Man, Donut Plains 3
is impossible.
Battle mode?
[Sighs]
Yeah, you're on.
All right.
Oh, Jesus.
All right,
you got to pick a guy.
What, Toad? Really?
Mm-hmm.
He corners the best.
Interesting.
Okay, there's a decent chance
this is gonna make me barf.
You and Joanie are
in the same boat this morning.
[Sighs]
Whoa!
You can throw banana peels?
How'd you get so good
at this?
I got my hands
on a prototype cartridge
about a year and a half ago.
Man, you really brought
the Southwest in here,
didn't you, Gordon?
Easy.
How much longer
are you in town for?
I don't know.
Oh.
But if you want to see
the craziest thing,
you should swing
by the focus-group testing
for my new game.
It's like "Altered States"
but with market research
instead of LSD.
That damn game
better be good.
Of course,
right when I get a red shell.
Here.
You tell me
if it's good.
"Pilgrim."
Hm.
I'm glad you're doing
so well, Gordon.
[Sighs]
Thanks.
Yeah.
I'm doing
really, really great.
I mean, last night,
I got to be a human paintbrush.
I saw that.
You know, CalNect is --
it's kicking ass.
Well, I'm sorry that Loadstar
has to be the exception.
-I --
-Come on.
You know,
if I'm being totally honest,
as time wore on,
the browser just became
more of a side project
for me.
It's always
been Joe's baby.
Joe.
I saw him last night.
And?
Oh, Gordon,
it didn't go that well.
Well, that's probably
for the best.
For who?
For him.
[Horn honking]
Oh, shit!
What?
The girls
haven't left yet.
Haley, Joanie!
Come on! Let's go!
Gordon?
No, she never comes in.
Don't worry.
[Honking resumes]
All right, well, um,
I'll see you Wednesday.
[Door opens]
Mm-hmm.
Love you, too.
[Door closes]
Joanie, let's go!
[Knock on door]
Gordon?
[Door closes]
Oh. [Chuckles]
Uh, have you
seen Mosaic?
Yes.
I was surprised
it wasn't you.
Hey. Uh...
She may have gotten
into the [clicks tongue]
Dad.
Get out here.
Thanks for this.
Yeah.
Anytime.
[Door closes]
She rarely comes in.
[Sighs]
Shep: As expected, the flat fee
and unkept usage dinged
the overall revenue
initially,
but now we're
in the volume business.
The user base
just keeps going up.
Then this isn't a rebound.
It's sustained growth.
That's good.
Only problem is
the pipe's getting tight.
We're starting to clog
a little bit with all that data.
MCI hears
how well we're doing,
they're gonna want
to renegotiate
the sweetheart deal
before they give us
more bandwidth
on their twisted pair network.
We could balk
and try PacBell,
but at the end of the day,
we'd want to keep
our backbone provider happy,
whoever they are.
What do you think,
Gordon?
Uh, if MCI wants
more money, fine.
We've got it.
Let's give it to them.
AOL's not the only one
with deep pockets.
Let's stay ahead of this.
Shep, get a call in.
And, uh, Joe,
thanks for sitting in today.
[Door closes]
What is this?
Loadstar.
Is that
the finished browser?
You've just been sitting
on this?
Couldn't get around
to handing it in?
No. I finished it
last night.
So, it was, what,
a day of work?
Joe, I've been working
on this for weeks.
You know, you didn't have to sit
around and wait for me.
If you were in such a rush,
you could have hired
somebody else
to do the coding.
You don't get it.
I needed you.
We needed you to care,
and you didn't.
We had almost a year
on the Mosaic guys,
but we blew it,
and now...
If you had just been here,
actually been available...
Well, I couldn't be here.
That was the deal.
And it was a raw deal
for me.
And it's just a shame.
It's a shame that 5,000 miles
away wasn't far enough.
[Scoffs]
What is this about?
Look, I made this better
than it had any right to be,
and I did so while dealing
with a lot of my own stuff.
Oh, right, your game.
I'm sure that was tough,
being funded, promoted, coddled.
I've been alone on this,
working by myself
for three years.
Do you want to talk about
what we're really talking about?
♪♪
If we had worked
on this...
together...
it could have been amazing.
[Sighs]
What do you
want me to do?
Nothing.
It's too late.
And I, um, got to get back
to work, so...
[Sighs]
You know,
the way things are growing...
you're gonna run out of
Post-its pretty soon.
Well, tell Oregon
they're not a big enough market
for Digital Subscriber
investments.
Let's get started.
Well, first off,
let me just say,
on behalf of the Rover
brain trust,
it's great
to see you again.
We're moving past
the beta phase.
We are already underway
in three med schools,
with requests
for two more.
A little more sobering,
though,
is that we've gone
through our seed round
just a hair faster
than expected, and now...
Now you need more money.
Vera: Well, yes.
It's either that
or we let some people go --
interns, mostly.
But this is still
enterprise software,
B2B currently focused
only on medical records.
Yes, through binary queries
into the data pool,
but we're refining comparisons
to make things more versatile.
Okay, I'll just cut
to the chase here.
I've given you enough funding
for a medical database program.
If you want more funding,
I will need a bigger idea.
Let's talk again
in 24 hours.
Uh, that's a mighty
quick turnaround.
[Chuckles]
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Joe: Gordon.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
What's up?
I've got something.
We can still
be the door.
Maybe it's not a browser.
In fact, it shouldn't be.
We're gonna build a website
that is accessible
from any browser.
Like a --
Like a website of websites,
an index of everything,
like a directory.
What, like the Yellow Pages?
Yes, but more than that.
I don't have the full
thing yet, but --
Look, Joe.
Joe, let me stop you
right there.
I thought you were back
on the business,
our business,
this business.
When are you
gonna wake up?
What?
You're sleepwalking.
I mean, what the hell
was that party, Gordon?
I wanted to celebrate
our success.
You're trying
to convince yourself
that it's okay to stop
when every fiber of your being
is telling yourself
to keep going.
I've been telling you for years
that you are a builder.
You need to build.
You know what, Joe?
I built this.
I built all of this
when you were downstairs
in the basement screwing around
with Post-it notes.
Did Cameron put you
up to this?
I noticed
that she stopped by today.
Of course she did.
[Door opens, closes]
Look, all we're asking
is that you put
the game's controls
in the manual.
-No.
-That's it.
No, the worst thing
you can do with a magic trick
is explain how it works.
No matter how much
the audience asks,
it's so much
more rewarding
if they get to discover it
for themselves.
You have to respect
the player.
Hey!
[Door closes]
[Door opens]
So?
[Door closes]
It's a trip, huh?
Cameron,
what are you doing here?
I told you.
I have to promote the game.
No, I mean,
what are you doing here?
This shit
was all behind us.
The browser?
Joe.
You have no idea how hard
he's worked
to get back to where he is --
how hard I've worked.
And now, all of a sudden,
you know,
you feel guilty
about no-showing on Loadstar.
You come back into his life
and you got him spinning.
-I didn't do anything.
-Look, you spent five minutes
with him in the basement,
and now he's convinced
that you've handed him fire
from the mountaintop.
Look, I'm not saying that
you're doing this on purpose,
but every single time that you
come back into his life --
I owed him that work.
I owed both of you.
You know, yesterday
you asked me if you were cruel.
[Knock on door]
Sorry. We only have the room
until 10:00.
[Door closes]
It was great
to see you, Gordon.
♪♪
[Door opens, closes]
Gordon: Yeah. I mean, isn't that
why God created hangovers --
teach teenagers
not to drink so much?
Drinking is one thing.
Okay, well,
it's better off at home
with one of us
than somewhere else, right?
Gordon, it's fine.
She told you
she's not going to college yet,
or is she still
just torturing me with that one?
It's a positive that our
daughter has such a free spirit.
Well, Joanie
is certainly resourceful.
You wouldn't believe the variety
of household items --
fruit, even --
she's found a way
to smoke pot out of.
Well, there's your selling point
right there.
She'd love Berkeley.
I'll talk to her.
Thank you.
It was weird to see Cameron
the other day,
especially
in your sweatpants.
Oh, well, you know,
she's always had a major, major
thing for me.
No.
Yeah, well,
I liked that you thought
it was even
a possibility.
You know what she said to me
about Mosaic?
She said, "I was surprised
it wasn't you."
What is that
supposed to mean?
I don't know.
Her latest visit's
got Joe jumping up and down
-about some new idea.
-Of course.
Yeah, I mean,
he suddenly thinks
he should index
every website in existence.
How would you
even do that?
Trust me, he's been meticulously
building a list of URLs --
by hand --
for the last three years.
That sounds
awfully tedious.
Yeah, well, you know.
Joe -- dog with a bone.
That he is.
And Cameron loves
to shit out rainbows
to distract
from her asshole behavior.
Wow.
[Clears throat]
I'm gonna do the salmon.
You?
Sounds good.
I'll do the same.
Here's to Mosaic...
and the respective death
of our competing browsers.
Good news.
We nailed it.
Magazines.
We use the algorithm
to index back catalogs
of major publications
one magazine at a time.
Voilà --
a trove of text documents
with an unstructured
data problem
just waiting
to be solved.
No, that's not it.
Oh. Uh, we also discussed
legal service --
backlogs of briefs
and precedents.
-Well, we --
-Look, this is all dead data.
What's growing?
What can we apply
the algorithm to that's dynamic?
We're in the future
business here.
I don't know
how we index live data.
Ah, well,
then that's unfortunate.
Cecil: Uh, well,
what about the Web?
The -- The number of websites
has grown 500% this year alone.
By next year,
it could grow exponentially.
At that point, the data pool's
theoretically limitless.
We'd have to adjust
the algorithm,
but we could endeavor
to index the entire Web,
make it searchable.
And how would you index it?
W-With the algorithm.
It'd be fully automated
and computerized.
That means it'd be up to date
almost instantly
with every
new site addition.
♪♪
[Sighs]
That's it.
That's the idea.
♪♪
[Telephone rings]
Joe: Don't tell me the reward
for solving Enso puzzle
was getting transported back
to the beginning of the game.
[Chuckles]
I'm afraid I've got some
bad news for you.
Oh.
So the Enso is a zero,
and I've got to start over.
Or maybe it means
everything.
Now you can approach
the path you've taken
in an entirely new way.
Mm.
I'm sorry
about the other day.
I was just having trouble
believing that the browser
was done,
and I know that
that is...over now.
I do.
Regardless,
I don't want five months
or five years to go by
before I hear from you.
[Sighs]
So don't
disappear again.
I want to...
know you in my life.
You already
know me, Joe.
[Chuckles]
I'm not going
back to Japan.
Tom left me.
♪♪