What happened?
He...
met someone else.
[Through telephone]
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are -- Are you...
Divorced?
I was gonna say "okay,"
but...
Oh.
Yes.
[Chuckles]
Uh...yeah,
I-I guess I am.
So, are you divorced?
[Chuckles]
Uh, almost.
You know, it's a pain in the ass
doing it from Japan.
So there's all these forms
and trips to the post office
and sending stuff to Texas.
And it all feels
like this weird dream...
[Chuckles]
...being married
and Tokyo...
[Sighs]
I'm sorry.
Do you want
to hear this?
I want to hear
whatever you want to tell me.
I feel like an idiot.
You're not an idiot.
Your impulsive, maybe.
Okay, Joe.
[Chuckles]
Hey, I'm impulsive, too,
so...
Are you, uh -- Are you
gonna stay in California?
I don't know.
I have to get out
of this hotel, though.
The shower sucks,
and I really want a bath.
I took a lot of baths
in Japan.
I love a good bath.
Yeah.
So, no hints
about this game, huh?
[Chuckles]
No. You got to
figure it out yourself.
Oh, but it's so hard.
It is until
you figure it out.
And then it isn't.
[Exhales]
Who was it?
Who was what?
Um,
the woman that Tom...
Oh.
Oh, that's, uh...
[Sighs]
That's the best part.
I never even asked.
Talk to me.
Tell me something.
[Chuckles]
Tell you what?
Just -- I don't know --
anything, life on Earth.
What'd I miss?
Well, what do you
want to hear?
Joe, just talk to me.
Okay.
Uh, did you know that
Bill Clinton is the president?
Yeah.
They love him in Japan.
All those cheeseburgers.
[Chuckles]
So, what else?
Um, the Cowboys won
the Super Bowl.
Audrey Hepburn died.
And so did River Phoenix.
Uh, some crazies tried to
blow up the World Trade Center,
and, uh...you can
be gay in the military,
but nobody
can ask you about it,
and you can't
tell anybody.
Did you know
IBM lost $5 billion?
They check
the couch cushions?
[Chuckles]
You know,
Gordon went through
this whole health phase.
He's got a room in his house
full of gym stuff.
Like, he's got
this NordicTrack
and something called
a ButtMaster, so...
[Chuckles]
And, um, this thing
happened to me.
I was getting out of my car
at a Safeway,
and I saw this woman
flailing her arms, just --
A swarm of bees
was attacking her,
just stinging her
again and again, you know?
And she fell
to the ground.
And out of nowhere,
this ice-cream truck
comes screaming
through the parking lot,
and it's playing that music
from The Sting.
And the guy gets out
of the -- the truck,
and he's doing CPR
and everything.
And the truck is still playing
that tinkling piano music,
and it keeps playing it even
after the ambulance arrives.
And it's all I could
think about for days,
these [chuckles]
paramedics
just working on her like crazy
while this music played
and how that might be
the last thing she ever hears.
♪♪
Cameron?
[Soft sighing through telephone]
Hey, Cam?
♪♪
[Sighing continues]
I'll just keep talking
'cause I think you're --
I think you're still there.
♪♪
[Sighing continues]
Are you there?
♪♪
I'm here.
[Rapid beeping]
[Tea kettle whistling]
[Whistling continues]
Hello?
[Click, whistling stops]
[Through telephone]
Hello?
Oh, hey.
Hey.
I was just making some tea.
Do you want to know
what your Hawaiian name is?
[Chuckling] Okay.
It's Kamelonu.
See, there's this whole website
where you --
You didn't hang up?
Well, yeah, I had to tell you
my Hawaiian name.
What is it?
It's just Joe,
but with an I instead of a J.
Eye-oh-ee?
[Clink]
I actually think
that's it's "Yo."
[Chuckles]
Right?
Right.
I'm not calling you "Yo."
[Both laugh]
[Clink through telephone]
That is such a Kamelonu thing
to say.
[Groaning lightly]
[Light thud through telephone]
San Jose is so weird.
You know it's actually
bigger than San Francisco?
I know, but it seems
so much smaller, doesn't it?
Oh.
I think I see a water park.
I haven't ridden
a water slide
since I was twelve.
Isn't that weird?
You might have already been
on your last water slide.
No way. I always planned
on buying up a water park,
living there alone,
riding the flumes by night.
[Laughs]
Yeah?
That's what you wanted to do
when you grew up?
Honestly, I feel like
I've always been a grown up.
Well, I bet you were
one of the only babies
with a chiseled jawline.
No,
there was one other kid,
but we fought
to the death.
[Both chuckle]
[Faucet turns on]
[Keypad beeping]
[High-pitched beep]
Donna: What do you think
about Rover?
[Fax machine humming]
Uh, um, Rover?
Um, they're...smart,
pivot on a dime,
good team dynamics.
Yeah, but doesn't it seem
like Elliot and Vera
just want to kill each other
sometimes?
That's because
they're married.
Huh.
Yeah, that makes sense.
[Sighing] Well...
you should just know that
they're gonna talk major shit
about you
on the drive home every night.
About me?
I'm making you
lead on Rover.
You pulled them
off the slush pile.
You've been doing the work
of an associate for months now.
You're ready.
Get them set up
in the Incubator today,
and start looking
for my new assistant.
Until we find one,
you'll be pulling double duty.
Congratulations.
This is typically where
members of the human race
express
some enthusiasm or...
Thank you.
[Light tap]
[Mid-tempo music playing
through speaker]
[Horn honks]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Indistinct singing]
Man: Bobby, yo,
grab it out of the car.
[Hinges spring]
[Door closes]
Who's winning today?
[Singing continues]
[Door closes]
Haley Clark.
Young lady, tell me
there's a good reason
you're not in second period
right now.
[Door closes]
[Singing continues]
So, he's from Philadelphia.
Joe: [Through telephone]
West Philly, yeah.
But his mom
is really freaked out
about what happened
on the basketball court,
so she packed up his stuff
and -- and moved him
to Los Angeles,
and he's been living there
ever since.
I'm sorry, but was the thing
on the basketball court
really that big a deal?
I mean,
to send your kid away forever?
I think it involved gangs.
-Oh.
-Yeah.
And he's not actually
royalty.
Joe: No.
"Fresh Prince" refers
to his street cred.
TV in Japan is weird.
[Laughs]
There's all these, like,
um, game shows
where they make you do
insane things
like, um -- like dress up
like a giant banana,
and then they drop you
into a zoo
with a bunch of chimps that
haven't eaten in a week.
And you're terrified,
screaming, running around,
but then there is this
[chuckles] studio audience there
who's watching
and laughing at you.
[Chuckles]
That sounds horrible.
You know,
I was on TV once.
Mm?
For IBM?
Uh, no.
I was 11 --
uh, Thanksgiving Day parade.
I was a pilgrim,
this other kid was wearing
his mom's brown tights
and construction-paper feathers,
and we chased each other around
a float and almost fell off.
[Phone beeping]
Hey, can you just --
Like, one second, one second.
[Keypad beeps]
[Grunts]
Hello?
-Hello?
-Hey.
[Receiver clicks
through telephone]
I was on TV
when I was a kid.
"Good Morning Dallas."
Troubled-youth exposé?
No.
[Chuckles]
I won a beauty contest.
You...
You what?
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
Little Miss Flawless,
1970.
My mom, um,
signed me up for a pageant
after my dad died.
I think she thought
it would distract me
or, uh,
we'd bond or something.
[Chuckles]
And you won.
That time? No.
No, I lost.
But she kept
signing me up.
I told her I hated it,
but she...didn't listen.
That bad, huh?
What, a bunch of 8-year-olds
whitening their teeth
and getting ranked
on their looks?
Yeah, it was that bad.
So, you whitened
your teeth.
Oh, my God.
She had a whole box
of tricks.
Spray adhesive to -- to keep
your bathing suit in place,
uh...
[Gasps]
Oh.
Hemorrhoid cream.
Hemorrhoid cream?
Yeah.
Yeah, 'cause I'd, um, cry a lot?
Before the competitions?
I didn't want to be there.
I just wanted to go home,
and so I'd cry and cry.
And that puffs you up
pretty bad.
So my mom found out that
if you put hemorrhoid cream
all around my eyes,
it took the puffiness away.
So I could be normal again
and march out onstage
and do
the Pretty Feet Pose.
One foot forward,
one foot back,
hand underneath
the rib cage,
big, stupid smile
on my face.
[Chuckling]
And...I'd lose.
Until you won.
Yeah.
Little Miss Flawless,
1970.
Got all those flaws
taken care of.
[Knock on door
through telephone]
One sec.
[Vacuum whirring]
-Ms. Howe?
-Hmm?
A Gavin Greene from Atari
is trying to reach you.
Thank you.
[Door closes]
[Inhales deeply]
So, is there, like,
a Fresh Princess of Bel Air?
Is it dumb to get suspended
for skipping school?
It is, okay?
But we're not here
to debate that.
Okay?
Look, I know what it's like
to have an older sibling who
requires a lot of attention.
Okay, your Uncle Henry?
Total bonehead.
Always getting
into major trouble.
And -- And so, I kind of
flew under the radar.
[Birds chirping]
[Door opens]
Look, Haley...
[Door closes]
...if you want to blow off
some steam, fine,
just don't
be dumb about it.
You know,
this isn't you.
You're -- You're -- You're --
You're smart, you know?
You're -- You're our rock,
you know --
[Sobbing]
Oh, honey, Bug?
No.
I'm sorry.
-Look --
-I don't...
No, I'm sorry.
Look, it --
Look, it's -- it's not even
that big of a deal.
I'm -- I'm -- I'm -- I'm
not even mad.
It's --
[Knocking on window]
Oh, sweetie, did --
Shep,
I'm -- I'm kind of busy here.
Ah, hey there, kiddo!
Okay, look,
did I upset you?
Is it something
that I said or...
[Sobs]
No, I'm...
Oh, honey --
Kind of need you inside,
Gordon.
Shep,
what do you need?
Kinda need you inside.
Okay, well, I'll be there
in a few minutes, all right?
[Sobs]
Okay, sure.
Oh, Bug.
And we're on it.
No.
Probably going to be fine.
[Sniffles]
[Continues sobbing]
Shep: Busy signals
for users trying to log on,
the customer-service calls
spiking.
Uh,
throughput's at a crawl.
We're not talking
Chernobyl-style meltdown yet,
but we're in Three Mile Island
territory for suresies.
Hold on. Hold on.
Hold on.
All because of
the flat-fee model?
[Sighs]
I mean, are people
really spending
that much more time
online?
A lot of people
just leave
their computers
logged on all day now.
Hey, Bug, do you mind waiting
in my office for me?
We got three dozen users
who've been on for more
than twenty-four hours.
So kick 'em off.
We'd have to write
new code to do that
and then get everyone
to download a software patch.
Yeah.
We need more capacity from MCI.
Get me, uh -- Get me
Jon Volpi on the phone.
Uh, tried.
Can't reach him.
All right, well,
get me Alan or Dave
or that
Bobby Sobrato guy.
Uh, w-we tried them, too.
We can't get ahold
of anybody at MCI.
[Indistinct conversations]
Where's Joe?
Uh, he never came in.
We tried him, too.
It just keeps
going to voicemail.
Look, just --
Shep, we need
to fix it fast, okay?
AOL is breathing down our butts,
you know.
And if we don't give
our customers what they need,
they're gonna go
somewhere else.
[Door opens]
[Sighs]
[Telephone ringing]
[Groans]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Door closes]
[Conversations continue]
Do you know
how to work Excel?
Yeah.
Well...
can you put these
in a spreadsheet for me?
It's really important.
[Conversations continue]
Okay.
There's some quarters
in the top drawer
if you need anything
from the vending machine.
Okay?
I'll be right back.
[Conversations continue,
door closes]
[Sighs]
[Button clicks, computer hums]
[Keys clacking]
It just doesn't sound
like Haley.
I was sure the school got
her mixed up with Joanie.
Gordon: [Through telephone]
Yeah, no, I know.
I'm telling you, Donna,
I don't know what's going on.
She's never been
the crying type.
[Knocking on window]
Yeah, I mean,
it was that --
that -- that really
intense crying.
Where you try and hold it in,
but you can't,
and, you know, then you just
start going into convulsions.
Ah, maybe she's just
on her period.
No, Donna,
this isn't menstrual crying.
Trust me.
I know menstrual crying.
Yeah.
You know menstrual crying.
Look, do you want me
to talk to her?
No.
No,
I'll -- I'll handle it.
Okay, well, good luck.
[Indistinct conversation]
[Exhales sharply]
[Receiver clicks]
Saturday afternoon,
nothing but ocean.
Oh, Donna,
it was Goddamn beautiful.
[Chuckles]
So, I took
my little disco nap
and I had a dream...
Ah.
...that I was this --
I was this big, fat...
[Laughing]
...bald baby just sloshin'
around a manatee's tummy,
just, "Whoosh, fworsh."
But when I come to...
[Sighs]
...by God, the boat
is pitchin' and it's yawin'
and it's rollin'
like a drunk donkey.
Just a freak storm
out of nowhere,
just a wall of black blocking
my path back to the coast.
I'm lost.
And I'm thinking,
"Turn out the lights.
The party's over."
Then I started to panic.
Then I started to S.O.S.
like an S.O.B.,
and that's when these two
eggheads just come cruising up.
[Slaps table]
Unbelievable.
See, these two have a custom
GPS receiver on their boat.
That's the Global Positioning
System.
That is right,
Donna, yeah.
Turns out Fred and Bill
are engineers.
They made AMD
a lot of money
by making real expensive stuff
real cheap.
Not a bad skill set.
Right.
So we had a few beers,
and we get to talking.
And what we thought was,
why not take their idea
and scale it up?
Make something a guy like me
can buy off the rack?
Uh, doesn't Garmin
already do that?
Mm, yeah,
but them and Magellan
got a stranglehold
on the market,
and, Donna,
they charge up the wazoo.
We're talking about
disrupting the price point,
bringing the costs
way down.
It's interesting.
And, hey, I --
what a fascinating technology.
Mm-hmm.
It is, yeah.
I'll look into it.
Fred...
-Yes.
-...Bill...
-Mm-hmm.
...nice meeting you.
-Nice meeting you.
-Pleasure.
Yeah.
Man: Thank you.
Oh, uh, yeah.
[Chuckles]
Thank you very much.
Thanks, guys. Great.
I'll see you in the lobby.
-Okay.
-Beautiful. Okay.
All right.
[Men chuckle]
Yeah,
we'll see you back there.
-Yeah.
-All right.
-Cool.
-Well...
[Door closes]
...all right.
[Sighs]
Well,
give it to me straight.
I got to manage
my expectations here.
Well, um,
it's intriguing.
Mm.
[Sighs]
What are you looking for
out of this, Bos?
I mean, do you really want
to be the exec at a startup?
I-I'm just looking for
a finder's fee, you know?
I like connecting people.
And I like these guys.
And just -- I'm the market
for this kind of thing.
You know?
There's a lot of other salty
sailors out there just like me.
Okay. Well, you know,
I'll look into it.
Again, uh,
what a technology.
[Telephone ringing]
[Sighs]
Well, th-thanks
for having us in.
Thanks.
Nice.
Yeah.
♪♪
Hey, you, me, and Diane
are overdue for a dinner.
We should do that soon.
We should.
Let's do.
♪♪
[Door opens]
Okay.
Okay, I found it.
David was visited by
an exact vision of death:
a long hole in the ground,
no wider than your body,
down which you are drawn while
the white faces above recede.
You try to reach for them,
but your arms are pinned.
Shovels pour dirt
into your face.
There you will be forever,
in an upright position,
blind and silent,
and in time
no one will remember you,
and you will never
be called.
As strata of rock shift,
your fingers elongate,
your teeth
are distended sideways
in a great
underground grimace
indistinguishable
from a strip of chalk.
And the earth tumbles on,
and the sun expires,
and unaltering darkness reigns
[through telephone]
where once there were stars.
Jesus...
But that's not
the end of the story.
This kid --
his grandmother tells him
to go shoot all the pigeons
in the barn.
And it makes him
think about death,
and he has
this crisis of faith.
A-And nobody reassures him.
He is...surrounded
by this non-belief.
It's like a conspiracy,
and he's just wising up to it.
But he still has to shoot
all these pigeons.
And he does, he just shoots
the hell out of them.
And he picks up a dead pigeon,
and he stares at it.
And it's actually gorgeous.
And he decides
right then and there
that no God who would
give so much beauty
to such
a worthless creature
would fail
to let him live forever.
Like his faith
is restored.
Is that
what you believe?
I just -- I don't know.
I guess I...
I hope
there's something more.
Huh.
"Huh" what?
Just weird.
I never thought about you
as the kind of guy
who needed "more."
All right.
What do you believe?
Um, well...
I saw this shrine
in Japan.
And, uh,
the locals tear it down,
right to the foundation,
every 20 years.
And then they build it
right back up again,
back to
its original state.
And they've been doing this
for 1,300 years.
Nothing in it's
original anymore,
but it still looks identical
to the day it went up.
That's beautiful.
Well, no.
I mean, I don't think
these people are doing it
for some
spiritual reason.
I think
they're doing it
because they're holding onto
the process of it, you know?
The doing of it,
that that's all that matters.
That's what I think.
I don't know.
I've been trying to find
some solace in that lately.
How's that
working out for you?
Not that great, Joe,
but thanks for asking.
Um, I'm sorry.
That was --
That was unfair.
[Chuckling]
Yeah, it was.
Look, I'm forty-five.
I've got no family.
I work in a basement.
People aren't exactly lining up
for my spiritual guidance.
Is that
what this is about?
What?
Well, you said
you didn't have a family.
You don't want one,
do you?
[Sighs]
[Horn honks]
My dad died last spring.
Oh, God, Joe.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
And you know what
this is like, but...
You just start
to think about everything.
And when I was --
when I was fifteen,
I made this vow that
I would never have kids.
All because of him.
He was just...huge
and...imposing.
You know you're huge
and imposing, right?
He made me feel small.
Like I was...
less than nothing.
And I never wanted to risk
doing that to a child.
Uh...
And then he died.
And -- And I'm, like,
there at his funeral.
And there's hardly
anyone else there.
And he felt like the small one
all of a sudden.
And that made you
want to have a family?
It made me realize that
we are different people...
and, um...
maybe I would have
been better.
♪♪
You ever think
about kids?
[Sighing]
Yeah.
I just, um,
sprung it on Tom one day.
Didn't even
really think about it.
Just [chuckles]
"Let's start a family."
Such a stupid thing
to say to someone
if you're not ready for them
to take it seriously.
And he did.
Oh, I mean, he lit up.
I've never seen
someone so happy.
♪♪
And so we, uh,
started trying.
[Swallows]
And it didn't work.
And I was relieved.
[Laughs]
I was relieved that
Mother Nature made
a decision for me
that I was too spineless
to make for myself.
And I realized I was
just going through with it
because I didn't want
to disappoint him again.
♪♪
Sorry.
I shouldn't...have said that.
You know,
it is so good
to actually talk to you.
[Chuckling]
Yeah.
♪♪
You too.
[Door opens]
[Diane sighs]
I think it's gonna take a while
for me to get used to that.
I mean, come on.
"Aggek"? What is that?
It sounds like
a painful hiccup.
It does kind of remind me
of pond scum.
Oh, God,
Trip makes my blood boil,
even just his name.
[Mockingly]
"Trip Kisker."
Elias does like him,
though.
He's a star.
[Sighs]
Look, if we're gonna
position you
to take over the mantle
once I'm gone,
a little diplomacy with
the new star pupil won't hurt.
[Elevator dings]
[Clears throat]
So, how was it?
Be honest.
Oh, well [sighs]
it's a promising arena.
But I think
they're too late.
There's a lot of muscle
in GPS already,
and retail is tricky.
But I can do
some more digging,
maybe order up
an analysis.
No.
I think John could care less
about GPS.
He's just restless
and looking for something to do.
"Aggek."
It's the cry you hear when
you step on a tiny lizard.
[Laughs]
Hey, we can still
talk trash about Trip
behind his back,
right?
Let's circle back
on that later.
Oh, really?
I think now's the perfect time
to drill down on it.
I always prefer
to drill down
[chuckling] after
I'm circling back.
[Laughs]
[Indistinct conversations]
Curtis.
Shep: Yeah, well, I'm
pulling software guys to
handle support calls.
[Woman speaking indistinctly
through telephone]
And we've already had
some cancellations.
Well, call me back
when you do have an answer.
[Receiver clicks]
Okay, please tell me
you've talked
to somebody from MCI.
Yeah, we did.
I just did.
Uh, Barry Schnellham?
Schnell-ham.
Okay. Well, who the hell
is Barry Shhhnellham?
Uh,
Barry Schnellham is...
Interim manager of enterprise
solution outreach.
They're gonna
wait out the clock
and then squeeze us
until we cave
on a huge rate hike
for more pipe!
[Sighs]
[Indistinct shouting]
What...?
[Shouting continues]
Oh, it looks like
customer service...
[Telephone rings]
...just face-planted
again.
Barry Shhhnellham?
Barry Schnellham?
Listen to me, Shep.
You get on the phone
right now
and you tell
Barry Schnellham
if I don't have
Jon Volpi on the line
in the next five minutes,
I'm personally gonna
drive down to MCI
and put my Goddamn face
through his Goddamn fist!
[Shouting continues]
[Telephones ringing]
Cameron: [Through telephone]
How is he?
He's great.
CalNect is really successful.
The ISP sector
is growing like crazy.
No, no, no, no, no.
How is he?
Oh.
Uh, I think he's fine.
He doesn't
talk about it much.
It must be so scary.
I mean, h-he's, uh --
he's really, really happy.
[Sighs]
Or at least he was.
Until I told him
about my new web idea.
Which is?
So, imagine,
like, um,
a website of websites,
uh, a curated index that takes
you wherever you want to go.
Like the yellow pages?
No, it's -- it's
so much more than that.
It's like a --
It's a portal...
[Knock on door]
Wait. Wait.
One second, one second.
...is what
I'm thinking about --
Okay.
Cameron, hey.
Hi.
Uh, your phone's
been tied up all day.
Yeah, sorry.
[Indistinct conversation]
Um, you have a sec?
We need to talk.
[Through telephone] Nobody
at Atari wants to push forward
on a product that
isn't perfectly calibrated.
So we've decided
to push back for a time.
How much time?
Indefinitely.
Also, we're gonna, uh,
need a quote...
tonight.
Yeah, uh, I'll, uh...
♪♪
[Thud through telephone
[Exhales slowly]
Joe: Hey, Cameron.
[Breathes deeply]
[Voice breaking]
Hey.
Um...they're, uh...
They're gonna
delay my game.
Like, um...
indefinitely.
[Sighs]
Uh, they need some
press-release quote from me,
so I -- I should
probably go.
I can write it.
Let me help you.
[Laughter]
[Cork pops]
Yeah, well, we can
to talk about it more.
Trip: So then Judy
barges in room, right?
Yeah, yeah. [Laughs]
Completely unexpected.
Knocks over the glass
and completely ruins my rug.
[Chuckles]
Man: Ohh.
[Laughter]
Like that.
Exactly -- exactly
like that.
[Laughter]
Okay,
time to address
the over-educated elephant
in the room.
[Light laughter]
A formal welcome
to our new general partner --
Colton Marshall Kisker III.
[Clears throat]
We were certainly lucky
to nab you from Sequoia
last year.
And the JoyRide IPO -- 22x.
-Cheers.
[Glasses clinking]
Cheers.
Mm.
I've got
a lot to say,
but I don't want
to ruin good champagne
with bad rambling,
so...
[Laughter]
Great.
Trip: I'm honored.
I'm humbled.
And I'm ready.
I am.
I'm ready to really drill down
on monetizing my portfolio
while simultaneously cultivating
new and promising ventures
that provide big exits,
with LP's clamoring
to sign subscription docs.
So, thank you,
one and all.
[Glasses clink]
Thank you.
Elias: All right, fun's over.
Back to business.
-Yeah. Let's do it.
-Come on.
SparqPlug's Series B
term sheet draft
is available
for the curious.
Joyce, can you send around
the target for PulseMD?
Got it.
And Millennium
is a write-down.
Let's take a knee on the web
for now, yes?
Actually, no.
Uh, Rover is repurposing
their software for a web play.
They're getting set up
in the Incubator now.
And you're still
on point, Donna?
I made
Tanya Reese associate.
She'll take lead and
have an update by end of day.
Um, just to throw out
a quick suggestion --
Rover has enough runway
to rework their core technology
and index the entire web,
make it searchable.
It's low-risk,
high-reward.
Uh, sorry, I'm -- I'm
just getting caught up
on the particulars,
but seeing as the web
is rocky territory,
is -- is jumping back into
browsers maybe something --
Rover isn't developing
a browser.
It's indexing the web.
The whole thing.
[Chuckles]
Uh, could -- could we
circle back for a second
and drill down
on leadership?
So, Tanya Reese was
an assistant of yours
until today?
We're all aware
of that fact, Trip.
Absolutely.
I'm just -- just
getting up on my skis here,
but, um, does she have
a web background
or any managerial experience
specific to this play?
Tanya sat on my desk
for two years.
She's been involved
in numerous deals
and consequential in the success
of more than a few.
Not to mention the fact
that she pulled Rover
off the slush pile
to begin with, so...
Gilson: Just, um,
talking while I'm thinking,
uh, but since the web
is frontierland,
would it be
the worst idea
to bring in
an outside consultant?
I think Tanya
is perfectly capable
of handling
the challenge --
Elias: I bet Joey Winchester'd
be happy to come in.
You know who's available
is Michael Hottendorf.
Trip: Cass Reinhardt just exited
Sequoia three months ago...
Ooh.
...and he would hit this
out of the park.
-Cass --
-You know what?
If that's
what Rover needs,
I have the perfect person
in mind.
Let me just, uh,
make a phone call,
and I'll report back.
♪♪
Elias:
Hmm, okay, moving on,
QwellX's missed its quarter
by a bit.
Livermore Three can take about
two percent of our load.
Oh,
that's a drop in the bucket --
we're getting hit in the face
with a fire hose.
[Bosworth laughs]
It's like a Greyhound
bus station in here, Gordon.
Hey, Bos,
what are you doing here?
I don't know.
I just thought I'd stop by.
We didn't get much of a chance
to catch up on your birthday.
[Indistinct shouting]
Hey,
step into my office.
[Chuckling]
Okay.
Looks like you could
use a break.
[Shouting continues]
Hey, sweetie,
can you give us a sec?
Ma'am.
Well, pretty, young secretary
you got there.
[Door closes]
Yeah.
[Chuckles]
I thought the ISP business
supposed to be easy-breezy.
People running around out there
like their balls are on fire.
Well, you know,
we're, um,
we're going through
a couple hiccups today.
Yeah, I remember
days like that --
the old
bucket brigade routine.
By God, it makes you
feel alive, though.
[Chuckling]
Doesn't it, Gordon?
Doesn't it?
[Chuckles nervously]
Them blue -- Them blue men
were something, huh?
-Yeah.
-Their drummin'?
All their,
uh -- their blue?
Hey, listen,
uh, Bos, m-maybe today's
not a good time.
Can we grab a drink
in a few days or something?
Yeah, yeah, but --
um, hey, uh...
[Snaps fingers]
Gordon,
I need to, uh --
I need to borrow some money.
Diane and I were
looking to invest
in this
housing development.
She lost interest.
And I didn't.
Uh, so I put up
my own money,
uh,
without telling her.
[Chuckling] And then
I went in whole hog.
So, you know,
I-I put good money after bad
and bad money after worse,
and before you --
Well,
now I'm in the drink.
First bank note's due
in a week.
All right, well, I mean,
why don't you ask Diane?
I mean, she's your wife.
W-Well,
she's not my wife.
I'm not a kept man.
I got alimony to pay.
I'm paying down college loans
for the kids.
I...
I sold my boat
to pay this thing down.
You sold your boat, Bos?
Well, I mean,
how short are you?
Eighteen thousand...
for the first payment.
Bos...
Well, wh-why are you
coming to me?
Well, now, don't worry,
I'm -- I'm good for it.
I'm good for it.
No, I got this -- this GPS thing
that I'm working on.
And then I got, uh --
Oh, God, I got so much stuff
in the hopper right now, really.
I mean, I'm -- I'm just --
I'm just cash-shy,
just a little cash-shy.
So I figured
you had a --
You figured that...
since I hired
the Blue Man Group
that I must have cash just
falling out of my pockets?
Look, Bos, look, I'd give you
the money in a heartbeat.
But you live with Diane,
who works with my ex-wife.
And who has more money than
all of us combined, all right?
I can't get in the middle
of that.
Okay?
You're gonna have to ask her.
[Sighs]
I...
That'd be the end of us.
Things are choppy
at home.
I mean,
but Diane's it for me.
She's got to be.
Look, Bos, I-I-I got to get
back out there right now.
I can't...
[Softly]
All right.
[Indistinct conversations]
It wasn't
all about the money.
[Telephone rings]
You don't know what it's like
being retired.
Hell,
you just turned forty.
You got a dozen more tricks
up your sleeve no matter what.
I'm sixty-five.
♪♪
This can't
be my last thing.
♪♪
You're gonna have
to ask her, Bos.
[Indistinct conversations]
♪♪
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
♪♪
[Door opens, closes]
[Mouse clicking]
♪♪
[Coin clinking]
[Rattling]
[Door creaks]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Wrapper rustling]
Gordon: Haley!
[Indistinct conversations]
Come here.
[Door closes]
[Mouse clicking]
[Door opens]
Wh-What is this?
Oh, well,
I just took a little break
to make something.
[Door closes]
And I'll keep checking
for broken sites, but --
No, no, no.
It's fine.
Haley, th-that drawing
is awesome.
It's because
it's Halley's Comet?
Because I'm Haley?
Is that lame?
No, Bug, that's --
i-it's not lame at all.
[Mouse clicking]
You -- You
like Richard Pryor?
Well, yeah,
he's the best.
Haley, I had no idea
that you could do all this.
Well, markup language
is pretty easy.
Not like it's C++
or anything.
That pony is dressed
like a little pink cowboy.
It's actually a miniature horse.
So it's way cooler.
Ah.
[Mouse clicking]
[Telephone rings]
This is --
Jon Volpi.
On the phone.
All right, Shep.
Is rad.
-"Rad"?
-Rad.
This is...rad, yes.
[Chuckles]
[Scraping]
Joe: [Through telephone]
You ready?
Cameron:
Yes. Go ahead.
Okay, okay, okay.
"A game of this scope
can't be rushed.
The Atari team and I have forged
a fruitful working relationship
that will continue
to deliver
the engrossing
gaming experience...
[Blows]
...our fans demand
and deserve.
I am gratified by Atari's
commitment to the title
and look forward
to our ongoing collaboration.
In addition, I firmly deny
that I have an urgent desire
to scalp Gavin Greene,
scoop out his brain,
and shit in his empty skull.
[Laughs]
Yes!
I think
we should send it.
I mean, minus the, uh --
the last part, unfortunately.
Listen, I know -- I know it's
hard to swallow this right now,
but you are so good
at what you do.
[Chuckles]
Joe --
No, really.
Don't let that asshole
take that away from you.
He's a parasite.
You create.
You make something
out of nothing,
and I have always been
in awe of that.
And not to ruin
the moment,
but I really,
really got to piss.
Oh, my God, me too.
Okay.
[Receiver rattles]
Yes, Jon,
we understand that part, okay,
but our trunk lines
are totally clogged over here.
Now, we had a contract
that specifically --
Jon Volpi:
[Over speakerphone] And we'll
uphold that contract...
but that contract doesn't
explicitly codify
expansion.
Uh, Jon, Shep Gramaticus, here,
VP of Ops.
Uh, if this is a rate issue,
let's talk rates.
We want to engage.
It's crowded out there,
Shep.
Only so much bandwidth
in the ISP market.
Can't really say there's pipe
just laying around for you.
Look, we get it.
We'll break
our rate lock.
No.
Look, Jon, just level with us,
all right?
What do we got to pay?
Guys, I'm afraid you're
not hearing what I'm saying.
There is no more pipe. For you.
Period.
And if you gentlemen
need anything else,
Barry Schnellham
is your guy.
Take care, now.
[Line disconnects]
Man #1: Are we an ISP
with no backbone?
Man #2: We're already
hemorrhaging customers.
Be dead before
we switch providers.
Man #3:
Can they do this?
Why are they
freezing us out?
[Gordon sighs]
[Shakily] They're starting
their own ISP.
Oh, my God.
Shep: We need to retain
outside counsel.
[Sighs]
They can't do this.
They're a public utility.
They cannot
pick winners and losers.
Man #1: [Muffled]
We got to do something.
[Muffled] What?
[Sighs]
Gordon...?
[Muffled speaking]
Gordon?
♪♪
[Insects chirping]
Joe: Does this qualify
as drinking alone?
Cameron:
[Chuckles through telephone]
It does.
[Swallows]
Mmm!
[Chuckles]
[Bottle thuds]
Oh, do you see that?
What?
[Gasps] The moon.
Look out your window.
No.
I think the hill
is blocking it.
Ohh.
That's too bad.
It's so beautiful from here.
[Chirping continues]
♪♪
[Knock on door]
[Door opens]
♪♪
You missed the moon.
Oh, well.
[Donna sighs]
Southeast Asian today --
pineapple, lemongrass, and mint.
Thank you.
Tanya, stay a sec.
I, uh...
There's been
a slight change.
[Elevator dings]
[Indistinct conversations]
Bosworth: I kid you not.
We come up through that little
trailer I was telling you about.
We go through the woods,
naked as a jaybird,
playing a banjo.
[Laughter]
[Chuckling]
I kid you not!
It really happened,
the son of a --
Hey there, Tanya.
How are you?
I'm just getting acquainted
with these numbnuts here.
Good to see you, John.
Should we get started?
Sure.
Here's a list of short-
to mid-term goals,
up for discussion,
of course...
Of course.
...aiming at a product
that we want to deliver
within
the next couple of weeks.
[Playing over speaker]
♪ This bed is on fire ♪
[Door bells jingle]
♪ With passionate love ♪
[Indistinct conversations]
♪ The neighbors complain
about the noises above ♪
[Door bells jingle]
♪ But she only comes
when she's on top ♪
[Door bells jingle]
[Instrumental break]
[Music continues]
Here you go.
♪ Lai-i-i-i...♪
[Exhales]
♪...i-i-i-i-id ♪
So, do you know
what you want?
[Music continues]
♪♪