[Water dripping]
♪♪
[Horns honking]
[Water dripping]
♪♪
[Crying]
It wasn't about him.
[Sniffles]
I was sad.
And I needed to pour
that sadness into something,
and he...
happened to be there.
I was in the same room
as him.
♪♪
I just keep thinking about
everything he said to me.
[Sighs deeply]
You took his side.
You love him.
That's not true.
♪♪
Why should I
believe you?
♪♪
Because...
there's no loving Joe.
♪♪
He's impossible
to love.
♪♪
He's empty and...
he just becomes
whatever circumstance
needs him to be.
♪♪
Who are you?
[Knock on door]
Gordon: Joe!
Oh.
Wow.
This is perfect.
Didn't waste any time,
did you?
Is he here?
At the office!
You're not hearing me.
No, this is an opportunity
for you.
Mm-hmm.
We are willing
to restructure the deal, Jon.
Listen, just give me
five minutes of your time.
Uh-huh.
[Sighs]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Telephone rings]
Gordon,
I'm sorry.
I had no idea
what was going on.
Just got off the phone
with Volpi.
Of course you can get him
on the line.
He's not budging!
I'm trying PacBell.
There's nothing there.
You're too late.
The only play
we have left now
is to sell while
we're still worth something.
Don't say that.
We can still figure something --
Oh, spare me
the theatrics, Joe.
If you've been on the phone
for five minutes, then you know!
That is not what I want
to hear from you right now.
How's Cameron?
Yeah, I stopped by your place
this morning.
She looked, uh...
comfortable.
You know,
you can imagine my surprise.
You disappear,
I think you're upset with me,
and then turns out
you've been holed up
with a married woman.
She's divorced.
Almost.
[Laughs]
Almost divorced!
Th-That's beautiful.
Why are we talking
about Cameron?
Because I know
you two!
And it's like --
it's like --
it's like you're a train
and she's a train,
and you think,
"Oh, we're both trains.
We should
get along great"!
But then both the trains
are on the same track,
and they're both headed
right for each other,
and guess what --
both the trains
are carrying dynamite.
Look, I've seen this
a thousand times.
I know
how it ends.
Okay.
It's gonna explode!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's not --
We're bad
for each other,
and it's going to
be disastrous.
Yes!
What is this?
♪♪
Cameron: Mm.
[Microwave beeps, humming]
[Dishes clattering]
Hey!
I made you breakfast.
♪♪
It's cheese egg.
Cheese egg!
Mm-hmm.
Um...
I, uh...
wish I could
come today.
We're putting the final details
on the sale,
and Gordon's a little...
heartbroken, I think.
Honestly,
it's just fine.
It's such
a non-thing.
I'm gonna do my little
obedient-robot routine,
and that's it.
You should
swing by after.
♪♪
Gordon'll
get over himself.
[Microwave beeps, humming]
It's fine anyways,
'cause I have to --
excuse me.
Um, I'm having
a sit-down with Atari
after the panel deal
to talk next steps
on Pilgrim, so...
Oh, that should
go smoothly.
Yeah, I think
they're gonna come around.
I, uh -- I got
a present for you.
Me?
Mm-hmm.
For your video games.
♪♪
Oh.
Well, that's...
passive-aggressive.
Really? Is it?
'Cause I was --
I was aiming for blunt,
uncompromising clarity.
Oh.
You missed the mark.
You're loud.
Everything you do
is loud...
and messy.
Sorry.
Which reminds me,
you should unpack
the boxes today.
♪♪
I'm so sorry
for interrupting
your perfect catalogue existence
little life.
I feel like you, um --
you thought that was an insult.
You're a freak.
You know that, right?
Unpack.
You're like if somebody
gave Howard Hughes...
Unpack...your boxes.
...a copy
of "Siddhartha"
and he just
rolled with it.
You're like three bottles
of piss away
from building a perfect
antibacterial chamber.
See?
God, these work great.
I can't hear
a word you're saying.
[Laughing]
You're so annoying.
[Telephone ringing]
[Chatter]
Your car
will be here in 20.
The guys from StrongBox
are presenting at 10:00.
Also --
Do you have the proposal
from MultiLink?
It's on your desk,
but --
[Guitar strumming]
Good morning.
Hey.
Uh, the guys at TuneWorx
sent this in today
as a thank-you
for the IPO.
They know I play.
[Guitar strums]
Ah.
I talked to the guys
at Spyglass.
I thought
they weren't taking VC.
If I'm
reading it right,
they're going to license
the Mosaic code,
and if they take
anyone's money,
it should be ours.
Few weeks ago, you weren't
interested in a browser play.
Yeah,
well, you know,
the right browser
could have legs.
[Guitar strumming]
Been taking lessons
a couple years now.
[Strumming continues]
I mean,
I'm a good player.
I'll never be
a great player.
Oh,
don't say that.
[Clears throat]
I'll keep you in the loop
on Spyglass.
We could tag-team it.
[Guitar strumming]
Thanks.
Package came
for Cameron.
Joe: Great.
More stuff.
It's from Tom.
Just a couple more.
You okay?
Our hands were tied.
We sold high.
Got twice
what we thought we would.
Guess you can still navigate
the business world
when you're motivated.
We've got capital,
blank canvas.
I liked this place.
I know it doesn't
feel like it now, but...
this is
the start of something.
Our 11:00
will be here soon.
♪♪
♪ There's a dream they sell you
when you're young ♪
[Brakes squeal]
♪♪
♪ But they never tell you
when it comes ♪
♪♪
What's up?
Joe would like to talk to you
about the pro--
The index you made,
the -- the -- the guide,
the comet list thing.
I love it.
Thanks.
More importantly,
other people love it.
The traffic
is astonishing.
Yeah, honey, it's a really,
really good idea.
The idea, obviously,
was mine, the indexing.
I did that work by hand
over years.
What your dad
means to say
is that the execution
of that idea is wonderful,
and we want to buy it
from you.
Oh, Joe,
slow down.
Joe...
I want to build it
and make it into something...
real --
no offense.
I would migrate it to its own
dedicated server immediately
so there is
a seamless transition,
no interruption
in service.
I would do that today.
I did it already.
You want to buy it?
Uh, what he --
Joe's, uh...
Look,
you -- you did the work,
so it's only natural
that we would buy it from you.
That's -- That's --
That's how these things work.
Okay.
Buy it for how much?
We would begin --
I think a reasonable sum
would be $20,000.
[Stammering]
Can I talk to you
real quick?
[Door opens, blinds clattering]
Look, I thought you were gonna
offer her, like,
a-a gift certificate
to Blockbuster
or, like,
a hundred bucks or something.
You want to low-ball
your own daughter?
No, Joe.
You said a "nominal fee," okay?
She's 14 years old.
You can't give
a 14-year-old $20,000.
This website has...
I'm crushing your head.
...12,000 unique visitors
in two weeks.
That's unbelievable.
Ckk, ckk, ckk, ckk, ckk.
Chh, chh!
Chh!
I don't give
a shit.
She's 14 years old.
In 10 years,
she'll be 24 years old,
and this idea could be worth
a billion dollars.
We're not giving her
the money.
Okay? We can come up
with another idea
or a trust fund or something,
but we're not giving a her --
Yes,
that sounds great.
Yeah, we'll put $20,000
in a trust fund.
[Door opens, blinds clatter]
We talked.
And we think
that $5,000 --
I don't want money.
I want to work on it.
Deal.
What? Wh--
I want to be able
to come here and work on it
instead of going to school
for one period.
Well,
we could --
It can be
my independent study.
Mm.
No problem.
We'll wire that up right away.
Now, I understand
you have to get back to English,
so we're gonna
talk about this after school.
Gordon, we'll meet
at your place?
Sure.
[Indistinct conversations]
Is their firewall
as strong as it sounds?
Donna: Third-generation,
application layer.
They're very talented.
Put on
a good show, too.
Speaking of
putting on a show...
Look at him.
For all his quirks,
it's good he's a partner.
He brings in deals.
He's trying to outflank me
on the browser front.
Few weeks ago,
he shits all over Millennium.
Now he's cozying up
to Spyglass?
Well, he didn't mention
anything to me.
Maybe he just wants
to work with you.
Oh,
there's Nina Klein.
I should
go say hi.
You go ahead.
I'm gonna...
Man: Hey, Donna,
well-done.
Really good.
Grab a seat?
Yeah, we should.
Well, uh, [Chuckles]
Joe Lieberman can blow me.
Hey, Doom is just
the tip of the iceberg, okay?
That's the future,
full stop.
No. Sorry.
I'm not sure
I totally agree.
Look,
I haven't played Doom,
but it's not because
it's so violent,
because to me,
it seems boring.
[Scoffs]
You kidding me?
It's addictive.
Yeah,
it's a Skinner box --
a lot
of these games are.
They're slot machines,
so they'll keep you coming back,
but they're not gonna
fulfill you in any way.
Look,
all I'm saying is,
I think there's room
in the future
for more than just gory,
first-person shooters.
I think we have another --
another question.
Woman:
This question's for Cameron.
Hi.
I was wondering
if you could talk about
your new game, Pilgrim.
I saw the release date
was changed.
Yeah, Atari has been
a really supportive partner
in collaborating
on this game,
and they are just taking
a bit of extra time
to figure out
the best strategy.
But, um,
it's coming.
I'm excited
about it.
I think
you will be, too.
Do you have, like, a ballpark
time when it'll be done?
It's done now.
[Audience murmuring]
In terms of release,
that would be
a question for Atari.
Cool thing
about games you download,
in terms of release,
there's less overhead,
which means less interference,
meaning more blood.
[Cheers and applause]
Eugene: Do we have
any other questions --
Yeah, I mean...
Yeah, anytime you can
cut out a middle man,
it's a good thing,
right?
Like I said, I have
a great relationship with Atari,
a lot
of mutual respect,
but there have been times
in my career
where my choices
were not as respected.
W-- Okay.
If there aren't, uh,
any more questions,
I think
that about does it for us.
Uh, thank you all
for coming.
[Applause]
Um, thanks to our guests,
Tommy and --
I have a question
for Ms. Howe.
Hello, Donna.
I was hoping
you could talk a bit about
the relationship between
a creator, such as yourself,
and the business side
of gaming.
You seemed
to indicate earlier
that there was some difficulty
for you there,
and I was wondering
if you felt
you had any culpability
in that.
Well, it's inherently
a fraught relationship, right?
Huh. How so?
Well, in that
we have the ability
to create something
out of nothing,
and that can be threatening
to people on the business side
because...
they can't.
Well, in my experience --
and, granted,
I'm not the one
up there onstage
at the Menlo Internet
Strategy Conference...
[Laughs]
...but in my experience,
someone on the business side
could help shepherd a project
that's meandering or...
headed off a cliff.
Could be an ally,
no?
Seems like that relationship
should be symbiotic.
[Man coughs]
I would say
it's parasitic.
There's little regard
for the wellbeing of the host
because a parasite
can always scuttle away,
on to
the next warm body.
[Audience murmuring]
♪♪
[Clears throat]
Ok-Okay.
I think that does it. We are,
uh -- We're out of time.
Thank you all
for coming.
Thank you
for your questions,
and I hope we get a chance
to meet some of you outside.
[Applause]
♪♪
Well, yes,
I'm going to make the monthly.
I-I'm at the mercy
of the pay schedule here.
It's a consultant position.
Tanya:
How was --
Donna: Fine.
It was fine.
Yes.
Do we have
an update?
The algorithm is continuing
to pick up new pages.
It's effectively
charting the web.
Okay.
We're only searching URLs
and page headings but --
Why can't we search
the body of the page?
Elliot: That's the
ultimate goal, of course.
We're just
not quite there yet.
It's too much data.
W-With --
With current bandwidth,
everything just
grinds to a halt.
How effectively
can we search titles?
Vera:
Very effectively,
but the title
doesn't always correspond
with, um,
what's on the site,
so the results are...
You keep giving me bad news
with a smile on your face.
Do you know
that you're doing that?
[Scoffs]
You guys are invested
in this, right?
Well, they have been
up all night working on it.
And what do you have
to show for it?
Let's search
"president."
[Keyboard clacking]
No Clinton.
Well --
What I see
are generic president results.
My guess is that somewhere
buried among them
are results about the current
leader of the free world,
which is what I assume
people are looking for
when they type in
"president."
What we need is a sophisticated
rules engine in place.
What I see is
no rules engine at all.
You do know I used to be
an engineer, right?
They don't know
what's expected of them
unless you tell them.
I am counting on you
to make it clear
just how little time they have
to get this right.
Okay?
Okay.
[Door slams]
[Mouse clicks]
Oh, yeah.
Cool.
Okay. Pull it up,
let's take a look.
[Door closes]
I changed
the header.
Oh, yeah. I like that.
It's Comet.
It sounds like vomit.
Don't listen
to her.
It conveys speed,
a sense of wonder.
What is this?
It's --
Joe and Haley
are working on
Haley's website project.
It's replacing
my independent-study credit.
[Refrigerator door closes]
What? She gets
to miss school for this?
I want
to miss school.
You do miss school,
you just don't
tell anyone about it.
Hardy-har-har.
Hey, you know,
I think it would be helpful
if, like, we started out
with a bunch of categories,
and then --
But we don't want to make it
seem dry, you know?
We don't want
to make it feel like
anyone could have
organized this.
Right.
Yeah, it's a dumb idea.
No, no, what's so great
about what you've done
is its
personal touch,
the feeling that there is
a person on the other side,
creating this experience
for you.
Haley: Yeah.
That's what I meant...
Mom know about this?
No, she does not yet,
but I will be the one
to give her that information,
thank you very much.
...like education
or something.
Can I watch?
[Chuckles]
...like
informational sites...
Why don't we go,
uh,
caving in upstate New York,
you know, spelunking?
You're literally
shouting nonsense.
I got all this stuff,
you know,
and -- and I've
got time now.
We should go
on an adventure.
I don't want
to go to a cave.
Well, look,
Haley...
Um...
...spelunking?
You remember that project
you did about stalactites?
I'm cool with
whatever you want, Dad.
Oh,
that T-shirt.
That's wild,
I was listening to Ritual
on the way over here.
Mm.
Please don't try.
Wh-What about fly-fishing
in Jackson Hole?
Oh, hey! Someone just sent me
a new link to put in our index.
It's, um,
Smuth-ut.
You know, Joanie, we could
actually use your input here.
What would make a website seem,
you know, cool to you?
Well,
I think it's pretty cool
on "America's Funniest
Home Videos"
when guys get hit
in the nuts.
That's a great idea.
[Mouse clicks]
[Chuckles]
It's like some kind of
construction thing.
Gordon: We should do this.
The Appalachian Trail!
Next summer.
We can do the hundred-mile
wilderness of Maine!
Oh, n--
Oh, my God.
Oh!
Oh! Whoa!
Hey! Hey!
Take down that --
Sorry.
I'm taking it down!
Turn it off!
Shut it down. Shut it --
Whoa.
Yeah!
I'm sorry.
Turn it off.
Oh, there's another head!
Take it off!
Ugh!
Whoo!
There's another head.
Hide your eyes.
I'm not looking!
She's too precious,
you guys.
Get off of me!
God.
[Laughter]
Gordon: Okay, look,
that is inappropriate.
[Indistinct conversations]
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Yes, uh...
Yeah, let's sit down next week
and talk about it.
I'll have Tanya
or -- um, Ashley give you a call
with times.
Okay. You, too. Bye.
[Receiver clicks]
[Sighs]
What were you and, uh,
Richie Sambora talking about?
His summer
vacation plans.
Oh, well,
that must have been riveting.
Stop talking about Trip.
I don't want
to talk about Trip anymore.
Okay.
He is an asset and a partner
in this firm, Donna.
Yeah,
I understand that.
I guess I was just
trying to make sure
that someone
had my back.
You know this office
is a boys' club.
It is a boys' club,
and I made managing partner
without anyone holding my hand.
Does he have an advantage?
Of course he does.
But that has nothing to do
with you.
Your success here
is based on results,
and I don't think you kicking
the crap out of your team
is the way
to get 'em.
I came in here
to tell you
that your girl
from the Rover team --
she was crying
in the stairwell just now.
You might want to consider
a lighter touch.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Sighs heavily]
[Telephone rings in distance]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Door closes]
Okay.
Here we go...
So --
Listen,
I heard what you said
about strategy,
and I --
I'm sorry, let me --
[Chuckles]
I think
we should go first here.
Unfortunately, we don't know
how this happened,
but someone
at Electronic Gaming Monthly
got a hold
of Pilgrim.
You're kidding.
A review
came out today,
and we got our hands
on an advanced copy.
How is it?
It wasn't good,
to be honest.
♪♪
We were all
rooting for this game,
and you know
how fond we are
of you and all the work
that you've done.
♪♪
Are you just
gonna sit on it?
Releasing it
in its current form
isn't a viable strategy
at this point.
[Sighs]
That's crazy.
♪♪
What did it say?
I'll let you
read it.
[Briefcase unlocking]
♪♪
I promise,
our lawyers are gonna
get into it with the reviewer,
and whoever gave him the game
will be dealt with.
♪♪
I gave it
to him.
♪♪
I want to spruce up
the interface --
not too slick, but it should be,
like, clean and efficient.
And we should spread awareness
on the message boards.
Print ads, too, might be
worth a look down the road.
You seem really excited
about this.
I mean,
you should run with it.
Absolutely.
I'm committed to this.
No, I mean,
uh, you should take it.
Write Haley a check
and -- and take it.
Is this about Smut Hut?
I'll make my e-mail the
contact for the site.
No, no.
It's -- It's not.
It's just,
uh...
it's a lot of things,
okay?
I'm not sure
that I want this for her.
Oh, um...okay.
Uh...
You know, Gordon...
...I want us
to do this together.
[Stammers] You can't sit still
any more than I can.
Joe, I haven't been
sitting still.
You know? [Chuckles]
I've been busting my ass,
working on things,
things
that I care about,
and just
to let you know,
I have been doing it
without your help.
And I'm sorry
about that.
Mm-hmm.
It's a big shift,
you know,
and -- and it happened fast
and --
Nothing's shifted
for you, Joe.
You've had your eyes
locked on this,
on the web,
the whole time.
You push people,
Joe.
You did it
at Cardiff.
at WestGroup.
You do it
all the time.
You decide what's right
for a company or a person
and you push them whether
they're ready for it or not,
and I can tell you
right now,
Haley's not ready
for it.
Oh, shit.
I should go.
[Door opens]
[Doorbell rings]
[Soft music playing]
[Gasps lightly]
Oh, you didn't
have to do that.
[Chuckles]
Trip asked me
to bring this to you.
Letter bomb?
[Chuckles]
I'm gonna put this
in the fridge.
Do you need me
to do anything?
Uh, no,
just, uh...
pour yourself something.
[Music continues]
♪♪
[Refrigerator door opens]
[Refrigerator door closes]
[Knock on door]
Bosworth:
Knock, knock.
Hey, Bos,
thanks for coming.
Well, sure,
it should be fun.
I just felt bad.
I was such a --
I had a crappy morning.
I figured...
a little unwinding
would be good for morale.
Oh, no, look,
I get it.
The kids are gonna
get whiplash, though,
well, you laying 'em out
one minute
and invitin' them
to dinner the next.
But...[Chuckles]
Hey, um, you know you can always
come directly to me
if there's ever any trouble
with Rover, right?
♪♪
Trouble?
Elliot: Hello!
Hey!
There they are!
Hey.
Come on in!
[Chuckles]
You can, uh, grab yourself
something to drink,
and there's --
Oh, come here.
[Chuckles]
Pizza's on the way.
Hi.
[Chuckles]
[Inhales sharply]
Wow.
[Exhales sharply]
It's a really nice home.
Look at that.
Cab? Scotch?
Vera:
Oh, no, thank you.
[Exhales sharply]
Cameron:
"A ponderous mess."
Oh.
"It's Howe's
ego-encasing strategy
to put any understanding
of the game
completely
out of reach,
and then
blame the user
when they are unable
to grasp it.
Let me assure my readers,
you are not missing anything,
for this game
simply isn't any fun."
Why did you
send it to 'em?
I thought
it was good.
It's just one review.
It's not.
It's the review.
It's --
God,
the focus-group testing --
even you
didn't like it.
I haven't
finished it yet.
What did they say,
what -- what -- what's...
They're gonna take the game,
take the code,
give it to some guy,
retool it,
add -- I don't know --
probably a big-titted mercenary
decapitating people
or something.
Hey, hey, hey,
look at me.
You are
full of ideas,
and you are going to make
a lot of games that people love.
You need
to put this behind you,
start fresh,
and move on.
It's not
that easy for me.
I need to, uh,
take a breather,
just be by myself
for a sec, okay?
[Clears throat]
[Liquid pouring]
[Soft music playing]
Well,
here comes my famous salad.
[Chuckles]
There's candied walnuts in it.
That's the secret.
[Door closes]
Well,
it's safe with me.
Hey, monkey.
Everything okay?
No.
Dad's being a dick.
Can I
stay here tonight?
Uh, yeah, sure.
Joanie, this is everyone.
Everyone, Joanie.
Do you want some pizza?
Oh.
She made
her famous salad.
Did she call it
her "famous salad"?
Bosworth: [Chuckles]
[Sighs]
[Music continues]
At work today,
I found a website --
Guys, we don't
have to talk about work.
This is fun.
You're not on the clock.
Well, if we're not gonna
talk about work,
what we
gonna talk about?
Okay.
All right. I'm sorry.
Well,
I have an update.
Uh, the problem
we were having,
the --
the president problem...
Mm-hmm.
...Cecil came up
with a fix.
A --
A temporary solution.
Uh, Vera implemented
basic inference rules
that complement
the Boolean logic,
so when you type "president"
without "Clinton,"
you get
relevant results.
"Rock" will give you
climbing and music,
"chicken" will give you
Parmesan.
It's a Band-Aid,
but it works for now.
[Exhales sharply]
Well, what if we typed in
"dinner-table conversation"?
[Laughs]
[Light laughter]
Mm-hmm.
[Music continues]
Okay.
All right, I didn't want
to have to do this,
but apparently,
I do.
Oh. Look out.
Look out.
Here come
the big guns.
[Clears throat]
[Chuckling]
Oh, shit.
[Gasps]
But we are
going to relax.
We are
gonna have fun.
[Liquid pouring]
We are all
going to forget about
what a jerk I was
this morning.
Can I have one?
Oh, yeah, right.
Uh,
I'm okay, thanks.
No. Unh-unh.
This is mandatory.
Unless you're pregnant,
I don't want to hear
another word about it.
[Gasps]
[Chuckles]
[Music continues]
Oh, my -- Oh, my God.
I'm -- I'm so sorry.
No.
It's okay.
[Music continues]
Nice one, Mom.
[Bottle thuds]
Well,
I guess, um...
We're pregnant.
[Chuckles]
Bosworth: What?
[Laughter]
Hey!
Well, congratulations,
for God's sake.
Thank you.
Cecil: Salud!
Oh, my God.
That was so rude.
It's completely okay,
please.
Okay, well, let me at least
propose a toast, then,
after that horrible,
invasive, horribleness.
[Light laughter]
[Sighs deeply]
I remember when I was pregnant
with that one --
she loves it when I do this --
[Chuckles]
I was working at Radio Shack so
I could get a discount on parts,
Joanie's dad and I were building
our first computer,
and I was terrified
that my boss would find out.
So I went to a thrift store
and I bought just the biggest,
baggiest sweaters I could find.
Anyway, months go by,
and I think I've got this guy
completely fooled,
and then one day, he leans over
to me very casually,
and he says,
"Before you know it,
they'll be grown.
You kiss that baby
every chance you get."
♪♪
[Chuckles]
Well, he was right.
♪♪
[Voice breaking]
Anyway, [Chuckles, sighs]
you don't have to wear
any giant sweaters around me...
[Chuckles]
...but...
♪♪
You kiss that baby
every chance you get.
♪♪
I'm so happy
for you.
[Chuckles] Cheers.
Hey.
Cheers.Cheers.
Here's to
baby-smooching, then.
[Laughter]
Elliot:
To baby-smooching.
[Chuckling] Sure!
Tanya: Cheers.
Salud.
Vera: Cheers.
[Sighs]
[Door closes]
There you are, you little shit.
[Gunfire]
[Keyboard clacking]
Ohh! Hey.
[Theme music playing]
Sorry, I just needed
someplace to play.
I'll get out
of your hair.
You playing Doom?
Yeah.
[Scoffs]
Yeah, I guess this is where
everything's going.
You just...
kill everything.
It's pretty awesome,
right?
Yeah.
You've played?
Pretty good at it, too.
Deathmatch?
[Theme music intensifies]
God!
[Keyboards clacking]
[Gunfire]
[Growling, groaning]
Gordon, move!
You do know
the object of the game
is to not die,
right?
Ugh!
You bastard!
[Groans]
[Sighs]
[Theme music playing]
So, I, um...
I'm sorry
about the divorce.
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
Thank you.
[Chuckles]
There is something
cathartic about it.
You bet your ass.
It's that you get to
be divorced afterwards.
I was talking about
the game.
Oh, um,
yeah, yeah.
[Chuckles]
So, how you dealing
with all of it?
Good. [Chuckles]
You know,
for me and Donna, it was, uh...
you know,
those last few months,
the process and just
getting everything untangled.
It was --
Oh, my God.
It was really hard.
Yeah, I can imagine,
with kids.
For Tom and I,
it's been, you know,
as good as it can be,
I guess, but still, it's...
That reminds me, um,
you got a package out there.
Joe forgot
to take it with him.
Oh, I -- Okay.
I'll take it
on my way out.
[Pen scratching]
So, how's Joe?
Good.
I mean, you know, who knows,
but right now...
good.
Think you guys'll ever
work together again?
No.
That's a minefield.
Oh, he, uh,
is really pumped
about this Comet thing, though.
He showed me.
It's really cool.
I just can't believe
little Haley is --
Yeah, I told him
to move on without us.
[Pen clatters]
Why?
I don't know,
I...
Joanie says
it's 'cause I'm jealous.
Is she right?
Maybe.
Maybe I'm just jealous
that they had a new idea.
I mean,
I'm definitely jealous
that I'm not
a kid anymore.
You know, all that time
you spend worrying about
wasting it
on the wrong project,
or the -- you know,
the wrong person.
It's hard to think of
a better way to spend your time
than working with her
on something she cares about.
I wish my dad could have seen me
be good at something.
♪♪
Look, your teenage daughter
wants to hang out with you.
That doesn't happen.
Yeah,
I know, but...
[Chuckles]
You don't have to worry about
her turning out like me.
She has two awesome parents
looking out for her.
You've even got a mug
to prove it.
♪♪
[Crickets chirping]
[Keys jingle]
Gordon: Cameron!
Oh. Sorry.
Box.
Thank you.
[Horn honks]
[Breathing heavily]
♪♪
Hey, Cam?
Yeah?
It wouldn't be so bad
if my girls turned out like you.
I'd be proud of 'em
if they did,
you know,
as a dad.
[Horn honks]
Geez, Louise.
Haley's project's
pretty cool, right?
It's very cool.
Yeah.
♪♪
[Car door opens, closes]
[Vehicle departs]
♪♪
[Thud]
Oh, shit!
♪♪
[Vehicle approaching]
Hey!
No!
[Exhales sharply]
[Knock on door]
What's going on?
Can I come in?
Yeah.
[Door creaks]
Do you want
to work on Comet with Joe?
Yeah.
Then
there are conditions.
One,
you don't let him
or anyone else
push you around.
Okay, if you have an idea,
you say so.
If you don't like an idea,
you say so, okay?
Number two,
this is fun, okay?
And the second
that it stops being fun,
you say so,
and we both walk away.
Okay.
Promise?
Promise.
Cross your heart,
hope to die?
Yeah,
all that stuff.
Okay.
Where are you going?
We should get started.
Sweetheart,
it's midnight.
Well,
we have work to do.
Okay.
All right.
Your idea
about categorizing...
Uh-huh.
...it's smart.
So...
let's start there.
Okay.
They had the crowd
eating out of their hand.
I mean,
Diane was there.
They're slick.
And Rover?
I had the whole team over
last night
so we could open up
the lines of communication,
bat stuff around
outside the office,
went really well.
Uh, what's the endgame
with that site?
In what sense?
The finished product --
I'm just curious
how you're seeing that.
It's the first site you visit
every time you're online.
It's the page that gets you
where you wanna go --
[Whispering indistinctly]
I'm sorry,
is there a problem?
No, sorry, I just wanted
to flag something for you,
but we can circle back
to that later.
I'll swing by
your office.
Oh, no. If you have something
to share, be my guest.
Benji sent me
a link to a site
that feels like
it might be operating
in a similar space.
Just wanted
to make sure you were aware.
Benji, do me a favor
and see who's behind Comet.
Maybe there's a play
to be made there.
Benji: Sure.
[Indistinct conversations]
Thank you so much.
Oh, no.
I can get that.
Okay.
Uh, I actually
had one thing
I wanted to talk to you about
real quick.
Oh, good.
Uh, me, too,
but you go first.
Someone at work showed me
the comet list or Comet?
Yeah. Yeah.
What do you think?
It's good.
Yeah?
It's really good,
I just --
we have something,
a play that looks like
it could be part
of the competitive landscape,
and I wanted to make sure
you knew.
Part of
the competitive landscape?
It's a search algorithm,
basically indexing the web,
making it searchable.
It started
as a medical indexing software,
and they shifted
into web.
Oh.
They shifted.
When?
A little while ago.
Mm.
Look, it's the idea
the team came to.
I wanted to tell you
as a courtesy.
Well, why didn't you tell me
as a courtesy
when I mentioned our
indexing project the first time?
Well, you told me that Joe
was writing down websites.
You didn't tell me you were
building a company out of it.
So you're competing
with us?
Well,
we don't have to be.
I'm sure I can talk the partners
into buying you out.
Buy us?
Why don't we buy you?
Oh, well, Gordon,
you can't compete with us.
You're not capitalized
the way we are.
You don't have
the staying power, believe me.
It's Haley's website.
Uh, wait.
What?
Haley's Comet --
she made the thing.
We're building it
together.
When were you gonna
tell me this?
Right now.
Oh,
over second dessert?
Oh, yeah,
like you weren't holding out
on the news
that you stole our idea.
Oh, please,
I didn't steal anything.
You know everyone's
getting into this right now.
You can't keep things from me
about our daughter.
This just happened.
It just happened.
I'm telling you now. That's what
these dinners are for.
You want to have dinner with me
every night?
Well, no, not really.
I tried that for 15 years,
didn't exactly get all
the information then, either.
Oh, God. Yeah, we're really
playin' all the hits, aren't we?
This is not the kind of decision
you get to make on your own.
Listen to me --
Haley built it, okay?
And we're helping her
make it into something more,
and she loves it,
okay?
You want to crush that,
go ahead.
But when you
break the news to her,
make sure you to tell her why --
that Mommy's knock-off company
couldn't compete
with the one that she built.
Gordon, this is a bad idea,
I'm telling you.
Rover has the full weight
of the firm behind it,
it's got momentum,
and I couldn't stop it now
if I tried.
Listen.
We're building the site.
You do
whatever you think is right.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Laughs]
[Mutters]
[Menu thudding,
silverware clattering]
[Clattering]
[Grunts]
[Clattering continues]
[Cameron sighs]
What are you doing?
I'm unpacking.
[Grunts]
♪♪