[Door closes]
[Keys clatter]
Donna: Well, I was just
a little bit surprised
because, you know,
you'd struggled for so long.
So I just --
I have to ask --
Who wrote the new algorithm?
I mean, I did.
Though I gotta give
Bos credit.
He had a great idea.
Yeah,
we're calling it the, uh,
the "waiting room" concept.
People wait in line in life.
Why not on the web?
[Chuckles]
So I-I created
a-a queuing program.
Yeah.
Our crawler was rude.
I had to teach that sucker
some manners.
[Chuckles]
Well, uh,
you enjoy the party.
[Computer chimes,
keyboard clacks]
Joanie: No!
Oh, my God.
What is wrong?
[Sighs]
This is so annoying.
What is that?
Cameron's game?
I thought that review guy
was just an asshole, but...
[Keyboard clacking]
...this is actually
impossible.
Like, she doesn't want anyone
to actually win.
Well, did you try
all three of these?
[Ethereal video game music
plays]
They all take you back
to the beginning.
I'm getting ice cream.
♪♪
[Freezer opens]
[Freezer closes]
♪♪
[Cookie clatters]
Hey, you think
I'd make a good spy?
[Door opens, closes]
[Eastern European accent]
I leave message here on service,
but you do not call.
[Chuckles]
Why? Do you want to watch
something else?
[Normal voice] No!
I'm really into it.
-Yeah?
-Her accent is ridiculous.
[Eastern European accent]
How many times have you viewed
this moving-picture show?
Geez, I don't know.
Too many times.
I've lost count.
Four in the theater.
[Normal voice] Oh, my God.
Easy.
I like what I like.
[Chuckles]
I like that you like
what you like.
Totally makes sense that
it's your favorite, though.
What's that supposed
to mean?
Are you kidding me?
It's a motley crew
of dude friends pulling capers
with nothing more
than nerdy technical skills
and a dash of moxie.
Well...
"Functioning superbly does come
automatically to me."
Fortunes!
[Wrapper crinkles]
What did you get?
[Laughs]
What?
Let me see!
"An exciting 'tim'
is coming my way."
Damn it!
And I'll bet he likes
swing dancing.
Why swing dancing?
Yeah, isn't that the thing
that you do every Friday night?
Roller derby.
Seriously?
I don't even know
how you mix those two up.
Well, in my defense,
I was incredibly distracted
by how bad I wanted
to sleep with you.
Mmm.
Nice save.
Yeah?
Roller derby, huh?
That's hot.
I know.
You want to come tomorrow?
Yes.
Yes, yes, I do.
Oh, wait.
Yeah, I think I got
the girls tomorrow.
Okay.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe...
Maybe I'll see
if they want to come, too.
Okay.
Okay then.
Do you mind
if we rewind a bit?
I don't want to miss
any madcap adventures.
Oh, I think we've missed
way more than a bit.
[Chuckles]
[VCR whirs, clicks]
[Eastern European accent]
I leave message here on service,
but you do not call.
Oh.
One more time.
[VCR whirs, clicks]
[Laughs]
I leave message here on
service, but you do not call.
♪♪
And then the guy drove
all the way back to my house
to bring me the bag
that I forgot
'cause he said he knew
I loved my Yoo-hoo.
[Scoffs]
Can you believe that?
I mean, these people are
the nicest people on the planet.
I don't know why anyone lives
in the city anymore.
So you don't have to drive 30
minutes to get your groceries.
I mean...
Good point.
[Rock music playing]
We weren't totally wrong,
though.
What?
Comet.
Search was always
a land grab.
[Sighs]
But I thought we planted
a flag.
Now,
flush with all that cash,
Rover will be able to innovate
in ways that we cannot,
especially
with the current structure.
So I...
What I guess
I'm trying to say is...
you were right.
Algorithmic search
is the future--
[Glass breaks]
Ay!
Shit.
You okay?
Yeah.
I don't know
why we would wait to pivot.
♪♪
I think I'm gonna stay
at the Airstream tonight.
MacMillan: What?
It'll be 11:00
by the time you get there.
Oh.
[Chuckles]
All right, yeah.
Do what you want, but...
-What?
-I-I was really hoping
you'd come in to Comet with me
in the morning.
I want to have a-a brainstorming
session with Gordon,
and we could really use
your perspective.
Joe, I didn't mean
to get in your head
about the algorithm thing,
okay?
You --
-Forget it.
-You didn't. Rover did.
You should just keep doing
what you were doing.
You have a very...
unique approach.
One day, maybe two.
No. I don't want to get
in the middle of things with
you and Gordon right now.
I'm not asking you
to mediate.
I'm telling you it's important
that we keep things separate.
Cam, Rover is gonna kick
our ass.
That's not my fault!
[Scoffs]
I didn't say
it was your fault.
I'm --
I'm asking for your help.
Yeah, now.
♪♪
I said
that you were right.
Okay, you and Gordon
didn't want me
to be a part
of your little club.
You weren't
even listening to me.
That is not true.
I asked you if you wanted
to be involved,
and you turned me down.
I also asked
if you wanted to move in,
and you don't want
to do that, either.
I ask you out to the Airstream
all the time.
I can't stand up
in the damn thing!
Look, I've been
really understanding with you,
beyond patient.
[Scoffs]
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize
we were running a tab.
[Door opens, closes]
♪♪
[Wok clatters]
[Birds chirping]
♪♪
[Sighs softly]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Air hockey puck clacking]
[Door closes]
Hey,
I got Katie on the ropes.
Herman:
Oh, I'm letting him win.
Oh, please.
Get a load of this wrist!
Aah!
[Laughing] No!
[Indistinct conversations
continue]
[Keyboard clacks]
Oh, look at that one!
[Laughs]
[Puck clacking]
Oh!
Oh.
[Telephone rings in distance]
[Sighs]
Gordon!
What?
I can't hear myself think.
You wanted the thing.
You picked the place for it.
Look.
It's Friday, okay?
All but two teams
have clear queues.
Maybe take a break
from thinking.
So now when I put in
"Dallas Cowboys,"
the first results
are the top fan sites.
Okay, so they've improved.
That was inevitable.
It's the next few results
where we're in trouble.
The Chisholm Trail
Historic Society.
The rankings
for the Texas rodeo circuit,
and, of course,
the country-Tejano
crossover classic,
"Mercy Me,"
by our friends
the Dallas Cowboys.
[MIDI music plays]
I don't get it.
I mean,
the last time we looked at it,
that was a bad thing.
Then they rank too high.
They've managed
to make the results
accurate
for the average user
while still accounting
for the outlier.
It's brilliant.
Well, if the results
are that impressive, then --
They are!
We need to build out
our coding team,
hire analysts,
statisticians.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look.
This is a much larger
conversation.
So let's have it.
[Laughter in distance]
It-- It's Friday.
And most of the queues
are clear.
[Indistinct conversations]
Okay.
Growth has slowed.
Yet we're still growing.
Not for long with this.
No, I think
you're overstating things.
Look, I get it
if you don't think
we're gonna be able
to pay for it.
I think you were right
the first time.
What we have is working.
Comet is great.
Okay?
Will you please just relax?
We sure are paying Katie
a hell of a lot
to play air hockey.
Okay.
What's this really about?
Ensuring the future
of this company.
Yeah?
Because from where I stand,
everything seems fine.
You, on the other hand,
walked in here this morning
like somebody took a dump
in your oatmeal.
Oh, yeah?
From where I stand,
it looks like
you don't care what happens
to this company
as long as you get to keep
screwing the chief ontologist!
[Indistinct conversations
stop]
♪♪
[Puck and slider clatter]
Why don't you get
some air?
♪♪
[Door closes]
Reese:
First wave of hires will be
in the engineering department.
Four programmers
by the end of the month,
a director
of product management,
and a Q.A. team by Q2.
You have fun last night?
Sure.
Sure, nice do.
Yeah, I was so wired.
I stayed up half the night,
looking at that algorithm.
It's just so impressive,
don't you think?
Cecil really came through.
On the top sheet,
you'll see we're outsourcing
the CFO role --
I mean, he solved
every problem he's been
wrestling with for months
in one elegant update.
Well, I guess the muse
finally had something to say.
Don't you wonder
what took him so long?
I don't.
Let's put a pin in expanding
the programming department
for now.
Cecil performed so well
under pressure, let's, uh,
let's see
if he surprises us again.
[Indistinct conversations]
Hey.
Um...
This is gonna sound
a little weird, but...
I got this song
stuck in my head,
and I can't get it out,
and --
Love this game.
Okay.
Go for it.
[Humming tune]
"Indiana Jones."
Definitely not.
Go again.
[Continues humming]
"It Takes a Lot to Laugh,
It Takes a Train to Cry."
That can't be a song.
[Chuckles]
It's exciting Tim's favorite.
I don't know.
Maybe I made it up.
I bet it will come to you.
Yeah?
When you least expect it.
Oh, yeah?
Hey.
I don't want to make it
more of a thing,
but Joe today --
Oh.
Yeah, listen...
There's really no excuse,
but sometimes,
Joe just can get --
It just got awkward
with Haley,
and maybe you should
talk to her.
What?
Did she say something?
No.
I'm sure she heard him,
so...
Well, she knows
we're dating, you know?
Yeah.
Dating.
You want me to have
a conversation
with my 14-year-old daughter
about my sex life?
No. No.
I don't know.
What?
Maybe!
She just got weird with me.
Okay, listen.
If you can't handle
a little weirdness with Haley,
there's no way you're surviving
trial by Joanie.
Fair enough.
Okay.
I'll pack extra padding.
[Birds chirping]
[Car door closes]
[Banging on door]
Oh!
Oh, geez!
Hey.
Hi.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Can I come in?
Howe: Sure.
[Door closes]
Hey.
Hi.
Coffee?
-Sure.
-Yeah.
[Cup clinks]
[Coffee pours]
You haven't responded
to my e-mails.
Howe: No.
I just haven't checked
in a while.
[Sighs]
Sorry. After everything
with Atari, I just...
Oh, yeah. I'm -- I'm sorry
to hear about that.
No, I know you worked hard.
Oh, wait.
You didn't come
all the way out here
'cause you were worried
about me, did you?
I had meetings
with a few developers.
Cool.
Many birds,
one transcontinental stone.
Oh.
So you are here to kill me.
[Both chuckle]
I just need you
to sign these.
Sure.
You couldn't mail them?
I did.
They were in the box with
your journals and the sweater.
Okay.
Wait.
Did you not get them?
No, I did.
Uh, it got hit by a truck.
Okay, Cam.
No, I-I know it sounds...
I...
I'll just sign
whatever you want.
This is insane.
Seriously,
she has lost her mind!
[Door opens]
Donna: Hey, guys.
[Door closes]
Just had a few minutes
and thought I'd check in.
Have Bos and Tanya
walked you through my thinking?
Bosworth: Uh, yeah, we're
working through that right now.
Vera: With respect,
we would prefer
to prioritize
programming hires.
Yeah,
I understand the instinct.
And in most circumstances,
I would agree. But --
It makes no sense to bring in
a head of business development
when we don't have a staff!
Hey, we're just
talking here, dude.
Vera: We're all grateful
for your leadership, Donna,
but I think that we have
more than proven ourselves.
And I would appreciate it --
Well, we would
all appreciate the respect
of being able to run
our own company
without this much
interference.
You are
an excellent programmer.
Thanks.
And considering
all you've accomplished
in the last couple months,
I don't see
a big value add
in additional engineers.
Yeah, I-I get that.
Um, but,
you know, I mean,
think of -- think of what
I could accomplish
if I didn't have to worry
about the cosmetic stuff
or the database.
It's just distracting.
And if I could just focus on --
on developing functionality,
you know,
who knows what's possible?
So you don't need programmers.
You just need coding grunts?
Uh, well, both.
We need both.
Well...
I want you to have
what you need.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You won't regret it.
But the idea of search
isn't proprietary,
and our process,
however, is.
So before we bring in
any outside talent,
why don't we get you
with our legal team
and file all
the necessary patents?
We did that
back when we got seed.
That patent was for a medical
records indexing method.
Do you believe that covers
Cecil's recent innovations?
The lawyers are gonna want
detailed specifications --
how it works, what it does --
in writing.
And I -- Don't you think we're
being overly cautious here?
No, I think I'm being the exact
right amount of cautious.
I assume that's not
gonna be a problem.
No.
No problem at all.
Once we lock down the I.P.,
you can have
all the engineers you want.
I'm telling you,
she knows.
[Sighs]
She's got her suspicions.
She can't prove anything.
Who cares
if she can prove it?
She can make my life miserable.
She already is.
You've gotta get it
the hell together, all right?
Get with the lawyers,
walk them through
how this thing works,
and then move on.
I know Donna will, too.
You're not hearing me.
I can't.
All right, there are these
chunks of what I wrote in there,
but the way it's connected,
I-I get what's happening,
but I can't explain it.
Whoever wrote this
is on another level, man.
-No, don't sell yourself short.
-Go ask him for the damn specs.
You know how to do all--
[Door opens]
You know, I'm kind of bummed
we're never gonna find out
what that sound was.
Oh, I never told you.
No.
What?
You're not gonna believe it.
It's an old woman tied
to a bed.
Close.
It's a parrot on a chair.
What?
A huge one.
A macaw, maybe.
No.
The screams were human.
I know.
Wait.
How did you get in?
There was a leak
in Shinsuke's apartment,
so Toshiaki had to open
the place up for a plumber,
and I just knew that
that was my only chance.
Oh! What --
What about the scraping?
It's a chair.
What?
It's the chair.
One of those metal ones
with the --
with the heart on the back.
The bird
would drag the chair...
from one window to another.
And at first,
I couldn't figure out why,
until I saw
that there's a cat in the alley.
So they had
this intraspecies game
of peek-a-boo going on.
It's so bizarre.
So a bird...
Yeah.
...drags the chair...
with its beak?
It's a big bird.
No, I don't believe you.
Well, why would I lie
about that?
[Sighs]
Where are you moving?
We got a place
in Setagaya-ku.
The suburbs?
That is...unexpected.
We're having a baby.
I'm happy for you.
Thanks.
All right.
You seem good.
I am.
Hey.
[Sighs]
♪♪
I'm sorry.
For all of it.
♪♪
Yeah.
[Birds chirping]
♪♪
Itterasshai!
[Mouse clicking]
[Sighs]
[Watch alarm beeps]
[Pen scratching]
[Pen clicks]
Hey.
I'm heading home, but you're
on my way to the rink,
so if you want me to --
Feeling all right?
Yeah.
Nothing to report.
7:00 at your spot?
You got it.
[Telephone rings]
Gordon Clark.
Hey.
Is he around?
He's not picking up.
Um, yeah.
Let me see if I can get him.
Okay.
Cam's on the line.
I don't even know what problem
I'm trying to solve.
Look, I don't know where he is.
Can I have him call you?
Okay.
Bye.
[Phone beeps]
Maybe we add a search bar.
Not with a crawler like Rover,
but we give users the option
to search our own index.
Okay.
I mean,
I could get behind that.
Yeah?
I don't know.
Hey.
What's going on, man?
I was just down there,
surrounded by Post-it notes
for three years,
and just when I feel like
I've got my arms around it...
I can't see it anymore.
So we're talking
about the future again.
I should call her back.
Is this what you saw
10 years ago?
Because it's not
what I saw for myself
when you showed up
in my garage.
That's the point.
It was never about
where it ended up.
It was...
about how it felt.
When I saw it...
I knew how it would feel
to build something with you.
But this --
Friday afternoon,
all the queues are clear --
I don't know
what comes next.
Most of us in the human race,
we don't get to know
what's next.
I mean, we just feel shit
as it's thrown at us.
This right now
is all there is.
Welcome to the future,
Joe MacMillan.
I mean, I can't speak
for anyone else, but...
I'm sure glad
to have you here.
Hey.
I'm really sorry
about earlier.
Hey, don't worry about it.
But if you ever scream
about my sex life
in front of my kid again...
I will rip off your head
and shit down your throat.
Search bar is a good idea.
[Clears throat]
We should do that.
[Knocking on door]
Hey, there!
Hi.
Hey.
Well, I don't mean to barge in
on you like this.
I been trying you all day.
Thought I'd take a flyer.
You know what, I'm just
in the middle of something.
Do you mind
if we talk later?
No, this won't take
but a sec.
Is Joe around?
No. He's uh,
on his way home.
Do you need to talk to him?
No.
Just you, darling.
Look.
I know what we said,
and I wouldn't ask, Cam,
if there's any other way.
No!
No. No. Bos, we said
no patches, no updates.
It was a one-time deal.
No, it's nothing that grand.
I just need a little help with
the tech specs for the patent.
What?
You're telling me he wrote
half the work,
and he can't explain it
to you?
Well, he could use
some guidance, huh?
Just a few minutes
on the phone.
Jesus.
No!
You promised me that this
would never come back to me.
No, and it won't.
It won't.
Cecil got no reason to spill.
Oh, God.
This is so stupid.
Why can't
you just talk to her?
Oh.
Sure, sure.
Soon as you tell Joe.
You really want him --
You want him to know
about all this?
[Sighs]
[Scoffs]
Look, Cam.
Okay, you need to leave.
Cam.
♪♪
This is gonna help
the both of us.
No, this was a mistake.
We don't talk
about this again.
Cam, please.
♪♪
Cam?
[Knock on door]
Cam!
Cam, please.
♪♪
Gould:
I should have let it slide,
but after a decade of pretending
to not notice him kick the ball
back on the fairway
like it was soccer...
I was either gonna
have to say something
or run him over with a cart.
Oh, God,
he must have been furious.
He covered well.
It took him two more holes
before he found an excuse
to wrap his nine iron a tree.
[Chuckles]
You know, I'm as competitive
as they come,
but I can't imagine what compels
a person to cheat so brazenly.
A long life of being told that
winning is your birthright.
-Hmm.
-John had a good line.
What was that?
John.
What?
About Elias.
Oh, yeah,
man's just a little lobster,
convinced he's king
of the crawdads.
[Chuckles]
Funny.
[Indistinct conversations]
Why don't you get the check?
Oh.
[Sighs]
I still can't believe it.
Well, yeah, it's about
time she stopped
letting that yahoo win.
It was killing
her handicap.
[Chuckles]
No, you know
what I'm talking about.
Let's take the night off,
Donna.
I mean,
it's miraculous, really.
The kid can't walk on water.
I had an idea.
It shifted his thinking.
That's all.
Just must have been
one hell of an idea.
And coming from you,
a tech expert such as yourself,
no less.
Well, it didn't take
no expertise.
I just figured you wait
in line in real life,
might as well wait in line
on the Internet.
Mm-hmm.
Cecil realized--
Our crawler was rude.
Yeah, we had to teach it
some manners.
Had to teach it
some manners?
You are so full of shit.
[Breathing quickly]
How many of those have you had?
I have enemies
all over this town,
and you bring someone in
to poke around my project.
What did -- What the hell
are you talking about?
Did it not even occur to you
that maybe someone out there
is trying to hurt me?
Sounds like you're nursing
a guilty conscience.
Oh, please!
Don't go trying
to turn this around on me.
I think there's
a reason why
you think I'm trying
to screw you...
You were being reckless!
...is that's all
you know how to do.
God damn it, I don't even know
who you are anymore, Donna!
I'm the woman who would have
fired your ass
if you didn't have
Diane's skirt to hide behind.
Well, shit, you've been hiding
behind her skirt for years.
Years!
I did you a favor.
The only reason I brought you on
in the first place
was because she was worried
you were bored!
[Mumbles, groans]
Bos? Bos?
[Grunting]
John!
Get some help!
Oh, my God. John!
Look at me!
John, stay with me.
Woman on P.A.: Morales,
please pick up line two.
Dr. Morales, line two.
[Door opens]
Doctor: Mrs. Bosworth?
[Door closes]
Mrs. Bosworth?
Actually, I...
Never mind.
He's gonna be okay.
All right?
Come with me.
[Exhales sharply]
Hi.
How is he?
Oh, he's -- he's stable.
[Sighs]
Okay.
They were doing a...
Um, I forget what it's called.
It's to check for blockages.
Diane's with the doctor now.
I'm sure there's more news.
Dr. Roberts, line four.
[Sighs]
Dr. Roberts, pick up four.
What happened?
I'm --
I'm not sure.
We were at dinner,
and he was fine.
And...then he wasn't.
[Exhales sharply]
[Sighs]
We had a fight today.
[Voice breaking]
I was mean.
[Sobs softly]
Well, you --
you can't blame yourself.
[Sighs]
What was the fight about?
♪♪
[Exhales sharply]
So it was you.
♪♪
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
He's gonna be all right.
He's a tough
son of a bitch.
Diane's
with the doctors now.
She's getting an update.
You okay?
Hmm?
♪♪
I don't know
what you're doing,
but stay out of my business,
and stay out of my life.
♪♪
[Door opens, closes]
[Music plays indistinctly
in headphones]
Joanie: Oh, my God.
I love her!
Herman: Right?!
[Both laugh]
Oh, God!
She's so bad!
[Laughing]
[Rock music plays
in headphones]
You want to listen?
No.
No, I'm fine.
Yo, punk, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Bos is gonna be
all right.
I'm just tired.
Can I borrow this?
Sure.
Haley.
[Inhales deeply]
[Cassette player clicks]
Hey.
[Sighs]
You headed out?
Mnh.
What you listening to?
Oh, nothing.
Show tunes?
Yeah.
"Pippin."
Hmm.
Really, though.
Uh, stress exacerbates
my symptoms, so, um...
this calms me down.
Enya, then.
No.
It's uh...
It's me.
I recorded myself
just talking,
reminding myself
that things aren't so bad.
That's beautiful.
We should all do that.
Can I ask you something?
Yeah, no, absolutely.
Is there a pattern
in your journals?
You know,
a few years back,
I-I got, you know,
really nuts about it,
and I put everything
into a spreadsheet
at the end of each week.
Then I had my friend, Gabe --
he built out
this statistical analysis
program
that would spit out charts
and graphs and reports and...
But...
[Sighs]
Hey, look, I'm really sorry
I missed roller derby
this evening.
[Scoffs] Don't be.
It'll be there next week.
It was nice to get some
good time in with Joanie.
She's fun.
She really likes you,
which is...something.
Hey, thanks for tonight.
You know,
I really appreciate it.
It's still early.
We can...watch a movie.
Um...
I'm really tired.
Okay.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
You sure?
Call me tomorrow?
Yeah.
Yeah, no, of course.
I'll --
I'll call you
first thing in the morning.
Pull over.
What's wrong?
Can you just pull over?
Please.
[Engine shuts off]
I saw John today.
Um...
He had some work here,
and, uh,
I had to sign something.
It doesn't matter.
[Sighs]
But I started
thinking...
about why
I finally told him...
about you and me.
'Cause at the time,
I thought
that it was the only way
to save us.
But now...
I think I wanted him
to leave.
♪♪
[Sighs]
I wrote the algorithm.
♪♪
I did it for Bos --
to help him.
He lost all this money
and he hasn't told Diane,
and it's a big mess.
♪♪
A part of me just...
wanted to see
if I could do it.
♪♪
I'm sorry.
Why are you telling me
this?
♪♪
Because I love you.
["Sneakers" plays on TV]
Bishop:
Okay, keep coming.
Emery: Oh, God.
I'm driving. I'm driving.
[Telephone ringing]
[ Vehicle crashes ]
[TV shuts off]
[Telephone beeps]
Donna:
Haley left her bio book.
Does she need it
for the weekend?
Hello.
Hi.
Do you know?
I don't, but can I have her
call you in the morning?
Sure.
It's, um --
It's been good for her.
Comet.
Yeah.
She's really growing
into her skin.
Yeah.
I'm glad you see it, too.
She's, um...
God, she's just
such a different person there.
Or not different.
She's just more --
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
Look, um...
I know it's been complicated
with Rover, but --
Look.
Donna, it's fine.
Tonight was...hard.
Yeah.
I can't imagine.
God, the sound of Diane's voice
when she saw him, it was...
And he and I had been
arguing.
I was really rough
on him.
Don't.
No, really, I...
I said some awful things.
Donna,
it's not your fault.
You weren't there.
You don't know.
Yeah, well,
he owes 300 grand.
Sunk a bunch of money
into a bad deal
and didn't tell Diane.
It's probably the real reason
he went to work for you.
You know, he came to me first
asking to borrow it,
and I turned him down,
so, if you're assigning blame
to anyone...
Donna.
You gonna be okay?
Sure.
Yes.
[Scoffs softly]
Night, Gordon.
Good night.
[Click]
[Phone beeps]
[Sighs]
[Insects chirping]
[Mouse clicks]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[PJ Harvey's "Rid of Me"
plays]
♪♪
Hmm.
[Key clacks]
[Mouse clicks, game chimes]
[ Breathing heavily ]
♪♪
♪ Tie yourself to me ♪
♪ No one else, no ♪
♪ You're not rid of me ♪
[Game chimes]
♪ Night and day, I breathe ♪
♪ Hah, hah, ay, hey ♪
♪ You're not rid of me ♪
♪ Yeah, you're not rid of me ♪
♪ I beg you, my darling ♪
♪ Don't leave me ♪
♪ I'm hurting ♪
♪ Lick my legs, I'm on fire ♪
[Keyboard clacks]
♪ Lick my legs of my desire ♪
♪ I'll tie your legs ♪
♪ Keep you against my chest ♪
♪ Oh, you're not rid of me ♪
♪ Yeah, you're not rid of me ♪
♪ I'll make you lick
my injuries ♪
♪ I'm gonna twist
your head off, see ♪
♪ Till you say don't you wish
you never, never met her ♪
♪ Don't you, don't you wish
♪ I beg you, my darling ♪
[Mouse clicks]
♪ Don't leave me ♪
♪ I'm hurting ♪
♪ I've been lonely ♪
[Game chimes]
♪ Above everything ♪
♪ Lick my legs,
I'm on fire ♪
♪ Lick my legs of my desire ♪
♪ Yeah,
you're not rid of me ♪
♪ I'll make you lick
my injuries ♪
♪ I'm gonna twist
your head off, see ♪
♪ Till you say don't you wish
you never, never met her ♪
♪ Don't you, don't you wish
♪ Lick my legs, I'm on fire ♪
♪ Lick my legs of desire ♪
♪♪