[Birds chirping]
[Utensil clinking]
[Utensil clanks]
[Microwave door opens, closes]
[Microwave beeps, whirs]
Hi.
Good morning.
[Sighs]
I got it: "Catch the Comet."
Oh.
No. [Laughs]
Why not?
Because it sounds
like the flu.
[Liquid pouring]
Or the clap.
How 'bout: "Let's Comet"?
How 'bout, let's not.
It's like Q-tip,
Kleenex, Band-Aid --
We could be
the first Internet brand.
Yes, and I would love
to be your focus group.
Just after 10:00 a.m.
But Rover's vulnerable,
one manager down...
Joe.
Come on.
That's a little evil.
It's a joke.
Relax.
Hey, I-I want us
to visit him soon, okay?
[Microwave beeping]
Mm-hmm.
He knows I told you,
and he feels bad...
I think
he wants to apologize.
There's no need.
[Sighs]
We still have
a better approach.
And as it turns out,
the "genius" behind
their new search algorithm
is unavailable to them...
Mm.
Cheese egg?
Wow. [Chuckles]
"Search it, find it...
com-it."
[Breathes deeply]
It's perfect.
Donna:
Thanks for coming in.
I thought it was important
that we speak face to face --
and in private.
I wrote ninety percent
of the code Rover's built on.
Yes, back when it was
a medical indexing company.
But Rover's evolved,
and you haven't evolved
with it.
I've done everything
you've asked me to do.
Why am I
the one that has to go?
Bos has already stepped away.
And frankly,
your deal is much more --
I made this company
with my friends.
Do you think I give a shit
about an exit package?!
We were fine
until you came in
and started demanding
the impossible.
If I've been hard on you,
I'm sorry.
[Breathes deeply]
But this isn't
about what's fair.
This is about survival.
I don't think
you care about the money.
But I do think you care
about your friends.
[Sighs]
The fact is, by passing someone
else's work off as your own,
you've put them
in a precarious position.
The only way to protect them
is to take
the search algorithm apart
and build Rover's own
proprietary version of it.
And for that to work,
you can't be involved.
I do know what it's like,
to feel like a failure.
To feel like
you don't measure up.
But if you don't step aside
and let me bring in
someone else,
you and your friends
could end up with nothing.
[Breathes deeply]
So what do I tell them?
The truth.
I'm burned out.
I've been struggling
for awhile now.
Rover's in a good place.
I feel it's time
for me to move on...
Try it.
I'm burned out.
It's been hard
for awhile now,
and I think
it's time to move on...
♪♪
Now...?
Take all the time you need.
♪♪
[Door opens]
[Dialing]
[Door closes]
♪♪
Haley!
Get over here!
What is it, Dad?
Well, we have
something really important
that we need to discuss.
Okay.
I think you know
what I'm talking about.
No. Uh...
Rockets!
No. Way!
Happy birthday, Bug.
Let's go this afternoon!
Well, slow down.
We can't.
We still have to recategorize
the site, and everyone's --
But the weather's perfect,
visibility's awesome!
Haley, come on.
And today's my actual birthday.
Yeah, but if we go Saturday,
we can invite your friends.
I'll ask them right now.
No, your school friends,
okay?
They have to work.
Besides, it's your birthday.
It's not a national holiday.
Okay, well,
what about inviting Katie?
Really?
Yeah, c'mon, let's do it.
Just us.
Let me see
if I can reach Cam.
I'll check to see
if she can move up the day.
You're the best!
[Dial tone]
It's not 100%!
This is
just so unlike Cecil.
Look, shake-ups
like this happen.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's no reflection on you
or on the long-term viability
of Rover.
But this will raise eyebrows,
won't it?
I-I mean, for a cofounder
to leave when the company's
doing so well --
Trust me, the only thing
anyone cares about
is how much traffic
we're getting.
And in that respect,
Tanya's right.
We're doing really well.
And with the Series A,
we have the opportunity
to attract
some formidable talent.
I want you guys to focus
on optimizing the site.
And I'll take lead
on hiring
and make sure we land
the best CTO in the Valley.
Is anyone good
even available?
Yeah, Bobby Aron is.
Bobby Aron?
Mm-hmm.
Are you kidding?
That guy's
a -- a legend.
Microsoft's making
a huge play for him.
I really don't think --
Listen to me.
We're the big ones.
Any CTO would be lucky
to be with us.
That's how we operate
from now on. Got it?
All right.
Yep.
Got it. [Sighs]
Okay. [Sighs]
[Laughs]
Hey.
How's it look?
Nice. El Gordo!
[Chuckling] Yeah.
You know what it means,
right?
Yeah. "Handsome."
Exactly.
Hey, you see that?
Uh-huh.
Haley drew it.
Sailors get one tattooed
for every 5,000 miles.
But you know what she said?
Since the rocket's 1/100th
in scale,
it only needs
to cover fifty.
Well, you haven't
launched yours yet, so...
What, do you honestly think
I'm not gonna launch
that thing 50 miles?
Fair enough.
[Laughter]
Katie:
No, don't worry, hon.
Do you think it's weird
that she didn't want
to invite
any of her school friends?
No.
School friends
are overrated.
Hmm.
She seems really happy.
And Katie is great.
I feel like
it's missing something...
Oh, you're planning
on going orbital?
Definitely exosphere
on this one.
Mm.
You guys do this a lot?
Yeah, we used to go
all the time
until my mom
blew her hand off.
It's just...
we didn't even see it coming.
You know?
You are hilarious.
[Laughs]
...so then, after I practically
promised her a kidney,
your neighbor makes
her poor son run ten miles...
One. One mile.
...just to come
and knock on your door
and give you a message?
So?
It's not like I didn't give him
a ride home afterwards.
Phones were invented
in the 19th century, you know,
when America
was still mostly agrarian.
Mm-hmm.
I mean,
you could build your own.
In fact, you should.
You're a lot of trouble
when you've got too much time
on your hands.
I told you,
I did that to help Bos.
He asked me for help, too,
but I didn't go out
and write him an algorithm.
Okay,
well, don't worry,
I'm done.
I'm sick of tech.
The whole thing.
What are you,
washed up at 32?
Come on.
You got one lousy review.
And do you have any idea what
people said bout the Symphonic?
Come on, I know you.
You dream in code.
Yeah.
Not anymore.
-Hey, guys!
-Hey!
-Guys, guys.
-We're ready!
Come on.
[Echo &amp; the Bunnymen's
"Seven Seas" plays]
♪♪
♪ Stab a sorry heart ♪
♪ With your favorite finger ♪
-All right, get your keys in.
-Key's in.
Hey, hey. Would you --
Would you film me?
♪ Paint the whole world blue ♪
[Laughs]
♪ And stop your tears
from stinging ♪
Happy birthday, Bug.
♪ Hear the cavemen singing ♪
And T-minus five...
♪ Good news they're bringing ♪
All: Four...
three, two, one...
♪ Seven seas ♪
Blast off!
♪ Swimming them so well ♪
Boom.
[Laughter]
♪ Glad to see ♪
♪ My face among them ♪
♪ Kissing the tortoise ♪
♪ Seven seas ♪
♪ Swimming them so well ♪
[Laughs]
Haley: Where'd it go?
♪ Glad to see ♪
[Laughter]
Where is it?!
I'm supposed to stop it!
♪ My face among them ♪
[Laughs]
♪ Kissing the tortoise shell ♪
[Cowboy Junkies' "Sweet Jane"
plays in background]
♪♪
[Door opens, closes]
♪ Anyone who's ever had
a heart ♪
What is this,
music to kill yourself by?
Hey, would you mind
bringing me a beer?
You can have one too,
if you want.
Don't tell your dad.
[Bottle cap clinks]
♪ And anyone
who's ever played the part ♪
So how's Bos?
Good, I think.
♪ Wouldn't turn around
and hate it ♪
And how's your first sip
of beer?
♪ Sweet Jane ♪
It's awful.
But he's good, right?
They released him yesterday?
How do you know?
I saw him Friday,
after school.
I thought visiting hours
at the hospital
were in the morning.
I told them
I was his granddaughter.
[Laughs]
I love that about you.
You know that, right?
You're absolutely fearless.
It's a hospital.
They're not gonna arrest me.
Well, I don't know
where you get it.
You never got
in any trouble?
Do anything crazy?
I was pretty cautious...
C'mon.
♪♪
[Laughs]
Well...
your dad and I used to go
camping all the time,
and we went
to this one campsite.
And the locals always talked
about this quarry they'd go to.
It was a swimming hole.
So your dad and I drove out
there, and we found it.
It was incredible.
It was this cliff
overlooking the glassiest,
clearest blue water
you've ever seen.
And your dad
wouldn't jump in.
[Chuckles]
He wouldn't.
It was too high.
So I laughed at him,
and he said,
"I bet you won't, either."
So before I could think twice,
I ran right up to the edge,
did a cartwheel right off.
Holy shit, Mom,
it's a miracle
that I was even born.
[Chuckles]
I guess
I just didn't believe
that I could really get hurt,
you know?
It just felt...free.
You have that,
and I don't ever want you
to lose it.
Don't ever stop yourself
'cause you're scared...
Okay.
♪♪
Well, next time I get
in trouble, remember:
It's 'cause
I'm being "brave."
[Laughs]
All right.
I got to do my homework,
so...
[Sighs]
All right.
G'night.
♪ Seem to whisper to me ♪
♪ When you smile ♪
♪♪
♪ La-la-la-la, la-la-la ♪
♪ La-la-la, la-la-la ♪
Joe:
It's amazing, isn't it?
One minute, Haley's four
and building a fort
out of the sofa cushions.
The next minute, she's...
Haley:
I'm crushing your head.
...telling
"Kids in the Hall" jokes.
It's just...so cool.
[water running]
Oh, yeah,
kids are great --
if you can give birth
to a fourteen-year-old.
I will see you tonight.
Bye.
[Door opens, closes]
[Mouse clicking]
[Keyboard clacking]
[Breathes deeply]
[Mouse clicking]
[Keyboard clacks]
What the hell...?
[Mouse clicks]
♪♪
[Mouse clicking]
[Mouse clicks]
♪♪
[Gasps]
[Mouse clicks]
♪♪
Joe: All right,
just relax.
Clear your mind.
Woman: Is anyone else having
problems with the monitor?
[Laughs]
Coward.
[Sighs]
Okay, uh, the first thing
that I think of
when I hear "Internet" is...
A computer?
A computer.
-And porn.
-Porn.
-Porn?
-Lots of porn.
I put in a request to be on
the team that catalogues porn.
Beep, beep, beep...
[Imitates modem static]
[Sighs]
[Ball bouncing]
[Ringing]
Gordon:
Gordon Clark.
Hey, it's me.
I'm sorry
this is so last second,
but can we reschedule dinner?
Yeah, no problem.
N-Nothing to report anyway.
Well, actually, there is.
Uh, I got a phone call
from Haley's
guidance counselor.
She's flunking history
and bio.
Our Haley?
Yeah, she hasn't turned in
some assignments,
and apparently she bombed
the last couple tests...
I don't get it,
she was doing so great...
Well, maybe she's just
trying to do too much.
Come on, Donna.
She loves Comet.
I know she loves it,
but I think she needs a break.
I'm afraid she's putting work
above everything else.
Hmm. Well, I wonder
where she gets that from.
Excuse me. I always put
the girls before work.
And if you need me
to talk to Haley
because you can't handle it,
then --
I-I --
I'm sorry, all right?
I just...
I don't want to be
the bad guy here.
And I do?
Okay, I'll talk to her.
Thank you, Gordon.
[Sighs]
[Telephone clicks in cradle]
♪♪
Whassup?
Haley: [Laughs]
Uh, it's a nice place.
It's...charming.
Yeah, thanks for stopping.
I was staved.
So...favorite site?
Um...
God, I can't pick just one --
That's too hard!
Uh, what did
everyone else say?
Well,
one person's favorite site
was a purple screen.
Just that --
a purple screen.
Melissa, right?
Mm-hmm.
[Chuckles]
She's obsessed.
And someone else
recommended
"Strawberry Pop Tart
Blowtorches."
Oh, yeah,
Arnie found that one!
We spent an entire day
setting Pop-Tarts on fire.
I think we destroyed
like three toasters.
[Chuckles]
That's impressive.
But I'm not sure
how any of these
are gonna get
the average person online.
Why not?
They got me online.
How so?
Well, when I first looked
at the Internet --
remember your Post-its? --
I thought
it was pretty boring.
It was nothing
but databases and archives...
But then I found
all this other stuff --
like this kid, Justin,
who's writing about his life.
And this other girl
who was obsessed
with "I Love Lucy"...
And what about that
was so appealing?
I don't know.
Um, school was not good.
I mean, no one was torturing me
or anything like that,
but it's just, like,
everyone's always pretending,
you know?
Mm.
That's why the Web's so great,
'cause no one pretends.
You just put it out there,
who you really are.
And if people respond to it,
that's great.
But if not, who cares?
At least they saw you
and not just some projection,
you know?
Yeah.
Vanessa: Hey.
Hey.
You guys working?
Uh, yeah.
Hi, Vanessa.
Um, this is my boss,
Joe MacMillan.
Actually, cofounder.
Cool. [Chuckles]
[Chuckles]
I'm totally addicted to IUMA,
by the way.
Their indie rock section's,
like, incredible --
I know.
It's like who needs Sub Pop?
Did you find
that Julep compilation?
The one
with the Bratmobile song?
Yes!
"Let's talk about...
dogs."
Dogs.
♪ Dun-na-na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Da-da-da, da-da-da ♪
Yeah.
-Yeah.
The Heavens to Betsy song's,
like, hella cool, too.
Yeah.
[Bell dinging]
I better get back to work,
but I'll see you later.
Yeah. For sure.
Cool.
♪♪
[Breathes deeply]
Woman on P.A.: Order 35, this is
your two deluxe combos ready.
♪♪
She seems cool.
Uh, what were
we talking about again?
So on the Internet...
you think you can be
who you really are?
With Rover we cannot only
count the number of users,
we can track what they click on,
how long they look at it --
I mean,
it's an advertiser's dream.
So, it is about selling.
No, it's [Sighs]
It's about change.
At Rover,
you could be part
of a universal,
decentralized platform
that's already
changing the world.
Look.
You could join Microsoft
and let them tell you
what the future will be.
Or you could join us
and tell them.
♪♪
[Sighs]
I accepted the Microsoft offer
this morning.
I only kept this meeting
because, well, growing up,
I was a huge fan
of Mutiny --
really Community.
I-I made friends,
and I traded bootlegs
and bought
and sold computer parts.
It was a lifesaver, really.
And I, uh...
♪♪
Well, I guess
I just wanted to thank you.
That's really nice to hear,
but I [Sighs]
I was really hoping
this would work out.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
Can I ask you a question?
♪♪
Community was so far ahead
of its time.
Why haven't you tried
to re-create it?
♪♪
Mutiny was
the most fun I ever had.
We didn't know
what we were doing.
It was one crisis
after another.
Hm.
But it worked.
The failure of that was...
Well, what's that saying --
You grow stronger
at the broken places...?
Hm.
Anyway.
Yeah, the truth is,
I am trying to build
another version of Community.
Except, this time,
it's the entire Internet.
It's everyone.
That's what's so exciting
about Rover.
It's flying without a net
into the great unknown.
Huh.
It's terrifying,
and it's exhilarating.
[Sighs]
Well...
I have been known
to change my mind, though.
Yeah.
Microsoft's safe.
But, um,
well, what's that saying?
No risk, no reward, right?
I'm in.
If you still want me,
that is.
I-I -- Y-- Absolutely!
Okay, okay.
[Laughs]
[Gasps]
I might need your shark side
to help me out, though.
The Beast of Redmond
ain't gonna like this one bit.
Oh.
They don't scare me.
Yeah,
I can't imagine who would.
[Chuckles]
To risk.
[Sighs, chuckles]
♪♪
Ahh!
Hey.
You up for one more?
[Dog barking in distance]
[Sighs]
[Groans, clears throat]
Ah.
Hey.
Hello.
[Clears throat]
Feeling okay...?
Yeah.
Uh, there's coffee...
I should, uh --
I should get going.
Yeah, we should, um...
We should talk
about the job --
You know...
it's fine.
Yeah.
O-Okay.
[Sighs]
["Jump Right Out
of This Jukebox" plays]
♪♪
♪ Suppose that
I should come to life ♪
[Knock on door]
John?
♪ When they play this song ♪
♪ I could be in a lot of places
at once ♪
It's from Sam.
Oh.
[Chuckles]
Aww.
That's me with all the hair.
[Both laugh]
♪♪
What a kid.
John,
this whole experience...
it's been making me think.
At the hospital,
it was so hard.
I had no say
in your care
and if something
had gone wrong...
Yeah, but it didn't.
I'm fine...
Well, it's not just that.
[Sighs]
At the restaurant,
there was a moment...
the way you looked.
I thought
I was losing you.
Oh.
I love you.
And I don't know how much time
together we have left.
So what're we waiting for?
Now, I don't have a ring --
And I know
you're expecting a big rock...
Goddamn, woman,
what're you doing to my heart?
So...?
♪♪
Do you remember the
Patterson housing development?
You passed on it.
I thought
it was worth a second look.
♪♪
How much?
300k.
I wanted to take care of it
myself.
I didn't want you to know
what a fool I was --
I thought workin' at Rover
would be a win-win,
and then we started hitting
a wall, and I panicked.
You saw the site.
It wasn't good enough.
We couldn't get over
that hump.
So I-I got Cam to help build
the search engine.
And Donna found out,
and then at restaurant,
she knew that she --
I'm sorry.
Diane.
♪♪
Diane!
[Indistinct conversations]
♪♪
[Breathes deeply]
Haley? C'mere.
What is it? Pete's waiting
to take me back to school.
We need to talk
about your grades.
Okay...
The school called.
They said that
you're failing two classes.
Failing?
I -- Maybe I missed a few tests,
but I can just retake them.
Well...
I'll talk to my teacher.
I can...
We agreed
that you could work here
if you kept up your grades.
That was the deal.
S-So what're you saying?
I have to stop working?
Just temporarily until you can
bring your grades back up,
and then we can talk --
But, Dad --
It's Haley's Comet!
You wouldn't even have
a company if weren't for me!
Hey, listen.
Calm down, Bug.
That's not entirely accurate.
Stop calling me "Bug"!
And why do
I even need school?
I already have a job.
Because you need school
to learn
and to make friends --
My friends are here --
And you can't fire me,
they need me!
[Chuckling] Okay, well, I think
we'd be able to manage --
Hey!
Haley, clean it up.
No.
Haley, if you ever want
to work here again,
you will clean. It. Up.
Haley!
[Door opens]
[Indistinct conversations]
Ha-- Hey!
Get back here!
Haley!
[Conversations stop]
[Door closes]
What?!
[Conversations resume]
[Sighs]
[Breathes deeply]
Yes,
it's a red leather wallet.
I was siting at the bar...
You do?
[Knock on door]
I-I will come by tonight.
Thank you.
[Telephone clicks in cradle,
door closes]
Do you have a moment?
What's going on...?
[Sighs]
I had a talk with John.
And apparently
he's made some bad decisions
regarding Rover.
But I think
you already know that.
Well, I [Sighs]
I had my suspicions,
but I didn't know for sure
until I saw Cam...
It's done.
Now, the important thing
is to clean up the mess
and move on.
I couldn't agree more.
Cecil is gone.
We plan to find someone
who can reverse engineer
Rover's code --
Reverse engineer?
Why?
Oh, to protect the site
from any liabilities --
But if Cameron
built this code,
the next step --
the only step --
is to get her
to sign a release.
That's how we protect
the site.
Yes, yes.
[Sighs]
But in this one case,
I really think
that is the wrong move.
I mean, why let Cameron know
how valuable
what she gave us was?
I mean, better
to just create our own version
of the algorithm,
and no one will be any wiser.
That doesn't make any sense.
Look, there is
one simple solution,
and it should've happened
immediately:
pay Cameron whatever she wants
and be done with it.
No!
I can't. I can't.
I-I just...
I-I can't.
[Sighs]
Well, this is
what's gonna happen.
You're going
to go to Cameron
and get her
to sign a release.
And then
you will step away.
And Trip will take over.
Th-- I...
That's not fair.
He'll just --
He'll -- You know him.
He'll use it!
To become managing partner?
Perhaps.
Maybe that's best.
Frankly, you have
bigger issues to deal with.
Get yourself together,
Donna.
I'm tired
of holding your hand.
None of this
would've happened
if Bos felt like he could
just come and talk to you.
[Door opens]
[Breathes sharply]
[Door closes]
[Sighs]
I was surprised
to get your e-mail.
I was about
to give up on you.
Yeah. Um...
So what is this about,
exactly?
You, um...
Did Atari send you or --
Oh, no.
Although
they were kind enough
to give me
a copy of "Pilgrim."
They did?
You can get anything
if you know how to ask.
I thought the game
was interesting --
flawed, but interesting.
I mean,
I've never played a game
that actively blocks
your way so much.
Yeah.
Well, I, uh -- I was trying
to respect the gamer.
Engage them,
not treat them like
a passive receptacle, but --
Respect, sure,
but you clearly didn't want
anyone to solve the game.
Why, I have no idea.
That's your thing.
But the world that you created
to contain the puzzles,
that was interesting.
And the graphics
were incredible.
I'm sure they still
don't even come close
to what you saw
in your head.
Well, the computer for that
doesn't exist yet.
You sure?
Processor speed is growing
at an exponential rate.
I've seen what's happening,
and it's mind-blowing.
'Cause here's the thing:
I don't think
you're a game designer.
Oh.
I think
you're a world builder.
♪♪
And I'd like
to work with you.
I want to see
what you do next.
♪ You're gonna wake up ♪
Okay.
And why should
I want to work with you?
Because here's
what I'm offering:
no VCs.
No interference.
What you said at MISC
was spot on:
The model is broken.
Parasitic.
So I plan
to stay out of your way.
While I do what, exactly?
Whatever you want.
♪♪
[Indistinct conversations]
You okay?
Yup.
You wanna talk?
Nope.
Hound Dogz.
We were just there
yesterday.
Yep.
She loves that place.
No idea why,
the food sucks.
Maybe it's not about
the food.
[Sighs]
When's she coming back?
No idea.
She no longer works here.
What did you do,
fire her?
I gave her a choice,
and she walked.
So get her back.
Joe, she's flunking
her classes
and copping
some major attitude.
You don't understand,
Haley needs this place.
She's not like other kids.
She's got different, um...
interests.
Well, good for her.
[Sighs]
She's a little like me.
When I was a kid,
I would've given anything
for a place like this,
someplace I could feel
like I belonged.
Yeah? Well,
this is what parenting is.
Setting limits, being
consistent, and discipline.
You sound like my dad.
Don't even start
to compare me to your father
because the two of us are
not even in the same universe.
All I'm saying is [Sighs]
he never really saw me.
He just wanted me
to be like him.
All I'm saying is that I see
Haley just fine.
Okay, I may not sit around
sipping milkshakes with her,
but I know
exactly who my daughter is.
Are you sure about that?
All right, what the hell
is that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
I just want
what's best for Haley.
Oh, come on, Joe.
You don't give a shit
about her
beyond what she can do
for this company.
You just want
what's best for you.
That's why you're not a parent
and you never will be.
[Sighs]
[Water splashing]
You're right.
[Door closes]
♪♪
[Glass clinks]
[Door opens]
Joanie:
Whoa, what level is that?
[Door closes]
Hey, guys.
How was school?
She had a fight with Dad.
What're you doing home
so early?
Uh,
I wasn't feeling well.
Oh.
Cutting work.
Nice.
We had a cool sub today.
-Oh, yeah?
-She's American,
but she went to college
in France.
Apparently, you can do,
like, some, like,
international-student thing,
and she said
it's, like, it was amazing
and that she saw these films
at the Cinémathèque,
and that, um, they have
all these, like,
really cool programs for, like,
film and photography, and --
Do you know what I love
about you, Joanie?
You are so...fearless.
You know?
Mm-hmm.
I hope you never lose that.
Just don't ever say no to
something because you're scared.
[Chuckles]
You want to
come play with me?
Come on.
I'll show you all my secrets.
It's okay.
I'm gonna, um...
I'm gonna go check with Haley
and see what she's up to.
-Uh, okay.
-Yeah.
♪♪
[Glass clinks, mouse clicks]
Where do you want to go?
[Telephone rings]
[Telephone beeps]
Hello?
Oh, Joe. Hey.
Hey, it's Bos.
Is Cameron there?
Uh, no.
Sorry.
You want to leave a message?
No, no.
I'll just...
I'll just call back later.
Hey.
How're you holding up?
[Sighs]
Well...
[Bottle hisses]
[Bottle cap clinks]
[Sighs] What a mess.
Well, I told myself
it was pride --
just stupid pride.
But the truth is...
I wanted to know
I still mattered,
wanted to know
I could shake things up.
Mission accomplished.
They is shook.
Yeah.
Well, I wouldn't know
anything about that.
[Chuckles]
You know, the things
that I've done...
[Exhales sharply]
I don't even know
why I did them.
I just wanted everything,
and I didn't care what
or who I had to go through
to get it.
Yeah.
That guy.
He was a real asshole.
I think I hired him once.
[Chuckles]
-Maybe I'm still that guy,
and everybody can see it
but me.
No. Recognizing you're
an asshole is half the battle.
But I've seen how honest
you've been with Cam.
That's a different man
than the one I first met, Joe.
I could've used
some of that myself.
Oh, we've got
our no-go zones.
Well, sure, you lie and say
you love the ballet or whatever.
Or maybe one of you
wants kids,
the other one doesn't
so you just
keep it to yourself.
Cam wants kids?
Mnh-mnh.
Well,
maybe she'll surprise you.
[Vehicle approaching]
She might surprise you,
too.
[Bottle clanks]
Good luck.
Wait.
[Groans]
[Garage door opens]
If you need a place to stay,
you're always welcome.
["We Belong" plays on radio]
♪ Maybe it's a sign
of weakness ♪
♪ When I don't know
what to say ♪
♪ Maybe I just wouldn't know ♪
♪ What to do with
my strength anyway ♪
♪ ...to do with
♪ Have we become a habit? ♪
♪ Do we distort the facts? ♪
♪ Now, there's no
looking forward ♪
♪ No looking forward ♪
♪ Now, there's no turning back ♪
♪ When you say
we belong to the light ♪
♪ Belong to the light ♪
♪ We belong to the thunder ♪
♪ We belong to
the sound of the words ♪
♪ Belong to the sound
of the words ♪
♪ We've both fallen under ♪
♪ Whatever we deny or embrace ♪
♪ For worse or for better ♪
♪ We belong, we belong ♪
♪ We belong together ♪
♪ We belong ♪
♪ We belong to the light ♪
[Siren chirps]
♪ We belong to the thunder ♪
♪ We belong to
the sound of the words ♪
♪ We've both fallen under ♪
♪ Whatever we deny or embrace ♪
♪ For worse or for better ♪
♪ We belong -- ♪
[Song stops, keys jostle,
car beeps]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Crickets chirping]
So...what happened?
I had two glasses of wine.
That cop obviously needed
to fill his quota --
our tax dollars at work.
But, I mean, um,
you've never even
gotten a ticket before.
Yeah, well, now I have.
[Laughs]
What?
Ah.
I was just picturing
my 22-year-old self
walking into AGGEK,
lugging the Symphonic.
She sits down, she pitches...
and I crush her.
[Chuckles]
The young me
doesn't stand a chance.
Oh, please.
That 22-year-old was hardly
sweet and innocent.
And the present you
isn't so ruthless.
And they're all you,
all the versions.
You're the same person
that you always were.
And...
I love that person.
[Sniffs]
[Crying]
[Keys jingle, car beeps]
[Engine starts]
♪♪
[Birds chirping]
[Keys rattle]
♪♪
[Parking brake clicks,
engine shuts off]
[Car door opens, closes]
Hi.
[Birds chirping]
Thanks
for letting me come by.
Sure.
Sit down?
[Exhales]
[Taps table]
Obviously,
we will compensate you.
I thought we could start --
No need.
[Cameron writes]
No payment necessary.
[Writing]
[Paper rustles]
Okay.
Well, thank you.
Don't worry.
I won't tell Joe.
He already knows.
[Chuckles lightly]
[Sighs]
[Breathes deeply]
Hey.
You okay?
[Horn honks]
[Birds chirping]
Thank you for this.
I won't
bother you again.
[Van approaching]
Hey, Pete, slow down.
I want to make a quick stop.
[Engine shuts off,
keys jingle]
[Rock music playing in distance]
♪♪
["I Found the Star" playing
on radio]
♪ I've not done anything at all
since I last saw you ♪
♪♪
♪ And I haven't had a thing
to eat for a day or two ♪
Vanessa: Welcome to Hound Dogz,
can I help you?
Yeah, let me get a, uh...
a breakfast burrito
and a small coffee.
Yeah, that'll be $2.80.
[Register beeps]
[Tray clatters]
Could I get a burrito
and a small coffee?
Man: Coming right up.
[Register opens, printer whirs]
♪♪
[Register closes]
[Birds chirping]
♪♪
[Keyboard clacking]
[Modem dials]
[Modem beeping]
♪♪
[Beeps continue]