[Footsteps approach]
Is she down?
Yeah.
Is it over?
Please tell me it's over.
I love my parents,
but, good God...
They're gone.
In an hour,
they will be in the air
on their way
back to Texas.
They are gone.
They are TWA's
problem now.
[Moans]
But, no. No!
Why?!
[Laughing]
Oh, promise me we will
never look at each other
the way they do.
Mm. I can't promise.
[Chuckles]
Sorry they drive you
so crazy.
What are you talking about?
They were great.
You see
what your dad got me?
The perfect reminder
of how unmanly he thinks I am.
[Electric knife whirring]
-Oh! Screechy.
Yeah, why we need
to improve upon a tool
that's been serving mankind
brilliantly
for millions of years
is beyond me.
[Electric knife whirring]
Dang.
This baby's really sharp.
Hey,
give me an old boot.
Let's see
what this thing can do.
Stop it.
You're gonna wake her up.
Oh, fine.
Oh.
I'm always amazed
at what my mom can do
with a glass of Chardonnay
in her hand.
She could join the circus.
Hey, you think
they had fun?
Yeah.
I'm not sure my mom
approved of the building,
or the neighborhood
for that matter, but...
you know, it's all about
appearances to her.
Yeah. And did you hear
what your dad said
about the peanut farmer
and his whole
energy-conservation diatribe?
No, don't. I can't.
Or the line about how we
should live in an area
with more homeowners
than renters.
You know
what that's code for.
Well...at least
they're good with Joanie.
Your mom
is great with her.
Well, so is my dad.
I mean, he didn't strike the
child, if that's what you mean.
Yeah, he also managed
not to set off any fireworks
next to her head.
[Chuckles]
It was one bottle rocket.
Oh, my God.
Did you see the look on his face
when Joanie spit up
on his special 4th of July Polo?
Hey, she was doing
that shirt a favor.
Oh, he tries to help.
He just doesn't always know how.
Offering to buy us a house
as long as it's in Dallas.
Oh, come on. I mean, would it be
the worst thing in the world
if we had
a little bit of help?
We don't need help.
Why? Do you want to
live here forever?
Look, Donna, we are not gonna
live here forever, okay?
Okay, we're gonna build
something, a machine, okay?
And we're gonna sell it
together.
Oh, yeah?
And when are we gonna do that?
Between nursing
and changing diapers
and being the only one that
can get the baby to sleep,
I don't really see
a whole lot of time
for building computers
in my future.
Gordon: Yeah, well, it's not
always gonna be like that.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
What's gonna change?
I don't know.
I mean, everything.
Well, I hope so, 'cause I don't
want to be breastfeeding
and doing dishes
the rest of my life.
Look,
it's been three months.
Well, in Texas,
I'd be freed up to go to work,
and so would you.
We're not actually talking about
moving back to Texas right now.
My mom said that
if we wanted --
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You've been talking
to your mom about this?
Well --
What, are you guys
making plans?
No, just...in broad,
hypothetical terms.
N-No, no, no, Donna!
Listen to me!
This industry is
all about who we know,
and if we leave,
we'll miss it.
Okay. That's not help.
Okay. That's --
That's offering
to kill us slowly.
That's a death sentence.
-No, they just --
They're seeing that we're
struggling is all.
Well, I'll do more, okay?
I-I-I'll help!
Oh, yeah?
Every time the baby cries,
you hand her back to me.
Okay. Well,
I won't do that.
Well, it's not just that.
It's -- I'm concerned
about everything
that she sees
and eats and touches.
And you -- you're exploding
fireworks next to her head.
Oh, my God.
Donna, it was one
goddamn bottle rocket, okay?
Look,
if you want to leave,
let's just pack everything up
right now.
No, I'm serious!
Let's pack
everything up right now,
and we'll move back to Texas,
and I'll go get a job
working for one
of your dad's friends,
and you can go play golf
with your mom every day.
That's
what you think I want?
I don't know
what the hell you want.
Okay, yesterday it was --
it was me
and -- and San Francisco
and building something,
and today, I -- I
don't have a clue!
You are being
so mean right now.
I would just like us
to stop and think
about one thing
we do before we do it.
I mean, we got -- we got
pregnant and then married,
and then we got
this whole life...
[Joanie cries]
...and I feel like
I haven't made
any of the decisions
to get us here.
Oh, you feel like you didn't
make any decisions?
Was I the one who got down on
one knee and proposed to you?
Oh, God.
[Crying continues]
Oh. I guess
I'll go get her, then.
No, just let her cry!
[Crying continues]
[Door slams]
Mommy's here.
It's okay.
[Crying continues]
[Keys rattle]
[Joanie crying]
Donna:
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
I know.
I know, I know.
It's okay.
[Crying]
Oh, baby.
Hey.
It's okay.
You want
your little elephant? Huh?
Yeah.
It's not so bad.
Okay.
[Door bells jingle]
[Pay phone dings]
[Car door opens, engine starts]
[Engine revs, car departs]
[Semitruck engine starts]
[Engine starts]
♪♪
[Door opens]
I don't understand
what the rush is.
The rush is I want to
get this over with.
I don't want to be making
a million trips back here.
So, whatever you want,
you should get today.
[Door closes]
Hold on.
So, for big stuff, furniture
we can't move ourselves,
green means keep,
red means donate.
Okay?
Green, yes, red, no.
Okay. Got it.
Start in your rooms.
Don't forget all your
schoolwork, textbooks.
Hey, guys?
I love you.
Love you, too.
Okay.
[Drawer opens]
[Doorbell rings]
[Sighs]
Hey, guys.
Oh, hey, hey.
How are the girls doing?
That's a stupid question.
We're all doing terrible.
Everyone's terrible.
How are you doing?
[Scoffs]
You know.
Uh, thanks
for helping out.
It's...
Of course.
Uh...
the service...was beautiful.
[Truck door closes]
-Yeah.
I thought what you said
was really nice.
Do you have
a copy of that?
I'd love to save it
for the girls.
I do.
Thanks.
Hey.
I wanted to say how beautiful
the service was.
Like, really personal.
Thanks.
So, what, um...
Where would
you like us
to start?
Yeah, God,
it's, uh...
kind of hard
to figure out.
Maybe you could tackle
Gordon's closet?
Just, you know,
throw his clothes
in garbage bags
for Goodwill.
Yes.
I'm gonna start
in the kitchen.
If you wanted to pack up
everything in here,
that'd be great.
Yeah.
Oh, I'd just, you know,
keep all the pictures
for the girls, I think.
They'll probably want them
eventually.
Oh, of course.
Yeah, right.
[Sighs]
Hey, uh...could you put
something on?
What?
Oh, it's too quiet.
Just something, anything?
Yeah, uh...yeah.
[Utensils clatter]
[Scoffs]
I don't know. Sorry.
Nothing feels right.
This is perfect.
[Dire Straits' "So Far Away"
plays]
♪♪
♪ Here I am again
in this mean old town ♪
♪ And you're so far away
from me ♪
♪ And where are you
when the sun go down? ♪
♪ You're so far away from me ♪
♪ So far I just can't see ♪
♪ You're so far from me ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪♪
♪ I'm tired of being in love
and being all alone ♪
♪ When you're so far away
from me ♪
♪ I'm tired of making out
on the telephone ♪
♪ 'Cause you're so far away
from me ♪
♪ You're so far away from me ♪
♪ So far I just can't see ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪♪
♪ So far away from me ♪
♪ You're so far ♪
♪ You're so far away from me ♪
♪♪
♪ So far away from ♪
♪ You're so far ♪
♪ You're so far away from me ♪
♪♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ You're so far away from me ♪
♪ You're so far ♪
♪♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ You're so far ♪
[Knock on door]
♪ You're just so far away
from me ♪
♪♪
[Knock on door]
Check this out.
[Laughing] Oh.
He loved this one.
This is from when we went to
that pumpkin patch in Garland.
Mm-hmm.
Can you believe
there was a time
that you got this excited
about pumpkins?
I still get excited
about pumpkins.
Pumpkins blow my mind.
You know, you don't have to get
rid of anything.
You could just...
pack up your whole room.
[Sighs] No, it's just,
I don't know where to start.
You need some help?
Yeah.
Let's start with your clothes.
That's easy.
Okay.
Oh, man.
So, just everything?
Yeah. I think so.
What's this?
USC?
Northwestern?
-Um...
What are these?
Are these duplicates?
You did send in
your applications?
I don't want to talk about this
right now, okay?
We are talking about this.
We're talking about this
right now.
Where are you going?
Leave me alone.
You told us
that you sent these.
What's going on?
Well, I didn't.
Can we talk about this
privately? Please?
Why? Why?
Why not here? Huh?
Why don't you let them see?
Why? Are you afraid
of what they might think?
That's enough.
Let's go outside.
No! Let them see
what a mess we've been!
And we have been.
I don't know why
you're doing this.
Your father would be --
he'd be devastated.
Well, it's a good thing that
he's not here to see it, then.
Oh!
That's...
That is --
That's a horrible thing to say.
How long did it take you
to use Dad against me?
Huh?
Like 10 days?
I'm surprised that you could
hold out that long.
[Door slams]
You are...
Sometimes I don't even know
who you are anymore.
We're all hurting.
We're all upset.
What do you know?
You couldn't even stand him.
[Footsteps departing]
[Door slams]
Cameron: Hey.
Joe took the first load.
Do you smell that?
Cigarette smoke.
I'm gonna kill her.
She wants to
piss you off.
Okay? It's the exact same thing
I would've done when I was 17.
I did my fair share of teenage
bullshit, but this is --
She wants to be a jerk.
Just let her be a jerk.
I don't know that
that's a strong enough word
for what she's being.
I mean,
she lost it at me.
Donna: She's the one
who didn't send them in.
Yeah.
I don't know if reason's
gonna be that helpful to you
in this situation...
or her.
[Sighs]
Probably shouldn't have
brought up Gordon.
Probably not.
I mean, was it not clear that
she disrespected me or --
Could I talk to her?
Yeah.
Tell her she's being
an asshole.
[Knock on door]
Do not open the door.
Whoops.
Hey.
Mm.
Really good one.
Your mom's totally
freaking out right now.
Yeah.
You don't get a million points
for subtlety,
but still,
it's very effective.
Mm. I wasn't trying
to do anything.
I just needed a smoke.
Mm.
[Water sizzles]
What's up?
[Door opens, closes]
Joe: Hello?
In here.
Where is everyone?
Oh...
scattered to the far corners
of the house,
some avoiding me,
others also avoiding me.
Do I smell
cigarettes smoke?
You do.
[Chuckles] Joanie?
Uh-huh.
How are you holding up?
Haley: What the hell?
Sweetie, what's wrong?
Dad's clothes,
where are they?
Oh, I just got back
from Goodwill.
Oh.
Honey, what's wrong?
Talk to me.
Dad's s-sweater,
I wanted to keep it, but...
It's the green one.
It doesn't matter.
I'll...
Forget it.
No, no.
I just got back.
You want
your dad's sweater?
We're gonna go get it.
Come on.
[Door opens, closes]
I bet she's more upset
about the fact
that she has to tell her friends
I'm not going to college
than the fact that
I'm not going.
Oh, Joanie, come on.
You know that's not true.
Everything's
appearances with her.
"Look at my perfect house
and my perfect pool
and my perfect daughters."
Did you know
she irons her jeans?
Okay.
Don't say things
you can't take back.
[Clears throat]
You need
to give her a break.
Give her a break?
Yeah.
You know why?
You're hard to navigate
because you're a dick.
And I say that
because I'm a dick.
I'm, like, huge.
I'm Queen Big Dick.
Like...
That sounded weird,
but...
-Yeah.
-...the point is, you two...
Just try and understand
where your mom's coming from.
And vice versa,
of course!
But, look,
when I was your age,
I cut my mom
out of my life, and...
you don't want to do that.
I mean,
I had a good reason to.
My mom was a mess.
Like, missed my graduation
'cause she drank too much
mouthwash kind of a mess.
But still...
[Sighs]
It's time
you can't get back.
I could stay with you.
The two of us
in my tin can?
Yeah. I could get another
trailer and take it out there.
It'd be awesome.
Oh, Joanie...
I mean, I can't even
take care of a plant.
[Chuckles]
I don't need to be
taken care of.
God.
Everyone looks at me like
I can't do anything for myself,
like I'm in diapers.
-Okay. I'm sorry.
That -- That's really
not what I meant.
I just mean...
This is why college
is so great.
You get to go and be by yourself
for the first time,
you can do whatever
you want to do,
smoke whatever
you want to smoke,
learn about the things
that interest you,
and if you don't know
what those are,
you -- you get to
figure it out.
I mean,
it's the perfect --
I know.
Joe: Hey, you want to put
something on?
What?
You don't have to listen
to your thing.
You can play it
on the stereo.
No.
You wouldn't like it.
I'm not that old.
Put it on.
[Cassette rattles]
[Barnes &amp; Barnes'
"Fish Heads" plays ]
♪ Fish heads, fish heads ♪
♪ Roly-poly fish heads ♪
♪ Eat them up, yum ♪
♪ Ask a fish head any... ♪
How'd it go?
Uh, good.
She's coolly awesome.
Managed to swipe these.
Hey.
Uh, these are Gordon's
grandmother's.
Gonna save them
for the girls.
Christ, I keep saying that.
I don't even know if they'll
care about any of this stuff.
They will.
Yeah, or they'll just...
put them in a box,
put the box in the attic,
and then, when they die,
their kids will pull it out
and say,
"I guess we should save this
for our kids."
Yeah, that's, uh...
pretty dark.
I finished the game.
What game?
Your game, "Pilgrim."
Uh...wow.
You "finished it"
finished it?
Yeah, finally.
You made it hard enough.
Yeah, I made it
for people like you.
Unfortunately, there aren't many
people like you anymore.
[Chuckles]
Well, I liked
the way it ended.
The pilgrim was a kid.
Yeah,
the pilgrim was a kid.
[Laughs]
Thank you for playing it.
Uh...
Yeah, it means a lot.
Hey, uh...
at the hospital, with Bos,
what I said,
I-I-I didn't mean it.
Please, Donna, I don't even
remember what you said.
Uh, yeah.
Um, I just mean
that I, you know...
me, I've been
in such a fog.
I can't even remember
my own name, let alo--
Yeah, no. Me too.
I'm gonna, uh,
go get another box.
Let's just go.
No.
Oh, here.
Is this it?
-No.
-Hey, hey, hey.
You can't be doing that.
What...
No.
We just dropped these off
an hour ago.
We, uh, put something
in here by mistake.
Man: Well, once you drop it off,
it's our property.
You know, I have no way of
verifying what's what or...
-These are just T-shirts.
-...or who's whatever and so on.
Let's go.
Okay. These clothes
belonged to a friend of mine,
and he's no longer with us.
There's exactly one item of
clothing that we're looking for.
We dropped off nine bags.
There's only eight here.
That sweater's in the ninth bag,
and we just have to find it.
Yeah, I mean, all this stuff
belonged to somebody, man.
There it is.
Hmm?
That's our bag
right there.
How could you know that?
You can't know that.
Look at that bag!
Now look at these bags.
Okay. They look like
trash bags, man.
I-I-I don't know
what to tell you.
I'm sorry.
-That's our bag!
It's just, this is
company policy, man.
I don't know what to say.
Let's go.
It is
what it is, man.
[Gravel crunching]
You've got your learner's
permit, right?
Yeah.
Pull the truck up.
Keep it running.
Okay.
[Car approaches]
[Engine shuts off]
[Car door opens, closes]
-Hey.
How you doing?
Super.
[Sighs]
Hi.
[Chuckles]
Mm.
Are you going somewhere?
I'm moving.
Got some friends
in Seattle.
I'm gonna give that a try.
They say it's great.
Yeah, yeah, I heard it's,
um...a whole scene.
Yeah.
I didn't know
you were going.
I told Joe and everybody
a couple days ago.
I, uh...
Sort of a quick decision.
I -- I'm sorry that I --
I couldn't stick it out there,
for Joe's sake, but, um...
There's just too much
of Gordon there at Comet,
and there's too much of Gordon
everywhere here.
Yeah.
Hey, you know, doesn't,
uh, sound that bad.
Car full of stuff,
a clean slate...
I suppose.
I've pinballed
around a bunch.
When I landed at Comet,
I thought that maybe I was
done with all that, but...
perhaps Seattle
will stick.
Do you know what's
gonna happen with it?
Oh, Comet. Uh...
I -- I think Joe will,
you know, carry it on.
I guess.
I hope so.
He really loves it.
With everything he's lost,
it'd be a shame
if that went, too.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go inside.
[Brakes squeal]
[Engine idling]
Go, go! Let's go!
Come on, man!
Go, go!
Go, go, go!
[Tires screech]
What is this?
[Splashing]
[Tires screech]
[Both laugh]
Haley: Holy shit.
[Laughing continues]
Possible that I --
I got the wrong bag.
[Laughs] Well, I -- I don't
think we can go back.
[Both laugh]
Oh, I, uh...thought you might
want to have this, so, uh...
Uh, yeah,
we had a lot of fun.
Gordon
was up for anything.
I mean,
I don't have to tell you.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
Well, he was just...
crazy about you.
It was a beautiful service,
by the way.
Yeah.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
Hey, uh, if there's anything
here that you'd like to have,
you should, you know,
please feel free.
Oh, uh, thanks.
I don't...really like
his decorating style.
[Laughs]
I never told him that.
It's, like, were you a vaquero
in a past life or something?
[Laughs] Yeah, I think, uh --
I think he had
a decorator do it --
a decorator with a fetish
for Navajo blankets.
[Chuckles]
You know
what picture I love?
There's this great one
of the two of you.
You're young,
and I don't know how old,
but you're both
holding beers and...
Gordon's got these
wild sideburns.
Yeah, yeah, I know it.
You both look like --
oh, man -- like -- like,
"Look out, world."
As soon as we got together,
I got very, you know,
"That's mine.
I want him all to myself.
I want all the Gordon
there is."
But you already had
so much of him...
You had...
hell-raising sideburns Gordon
and who knows what else.
And it made me jealous.
Well...I don't -- I don't know
what I'm saying.
Uh...
Goddamn, Gordon,
what the hell?
Well, I'm gonna...
get out of your hair.
Thank you.
Joanie's, uh, up in her room
if you wanted to say hi.
But I would, um...
proceed with caution.
Thanks.
I'll be careful.
Joe's been gone
for a while, huh?
Yeah, maybe they stopped
to get something to eat.
That's good. Haley needs to get
out of here for a little while.
Joe's been so great
with her.
Hey, uh, did you want the weird
priest statues or...?
You know, I already have
so many of them at home.
[Chuckles]
I always forget how good
Joe is with the girls.
Just really lights them
right up.
Because we're a team.
Hey.
Hey. Sorry.
You okay?
This is where I found him.
I'm gonna go.
[Door opens, closes]
♪♪
[Engine starts]
Hello?
[Door closes]
[Music plays indistinctly
in headphones]
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Hey. Bos just showed up.
He brought food.
[Sighs]
Mom wanted me to see
if you needed any help.
Mm.
I don't really want
any of this stuff.
Just my CDs
and my pictures.
What?
[Chuckles]
Why didn't you apply
to college?
Well, I wasn't gonna get
into any of them.
[Chuckles]
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
I'll figure it out.
Donating you.
[Chuckles]
Like to see you try.
[Laughs]
At least they have you.
Exactly what they want
in every way.
Well, not every way.
Come here.
Dummy.
Mm.
You're not gonna
go away, too, are you?
Joe, you ever have
my chili?
Oh, I don't know.
It's an old Bosworth family
recipe, handed down.
The secret's in the cinnamon.
Yeah.
See, what you do is,
you take that cinnamon,
and you put it
in the cupboard
and keep it away
from your chili
'cause it got no damn business
being there in the first place.
[Sighs]
You know, I remember...
I didn't really even
notice Gordon
until he started working
on "The Giant" with y'all.
I used to call him
Soup Stain...
[Chuckles]
...'cause he always had a --
I'm not...
ready to do that.
You do me a favor
and taste this real quick?
I'm not hungry.
I don't care
if you're hungry.
Just want to make sure
it's not too hot for the girls.
They been eating crap
all week.
I want to make sure
they get a good meal.
Just check the damn spice level
on that, if you could.
I want to make sure
everyone's gonna eat it.
It's good.
Not too spicy?
No.
It's really good.
Good.
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
Hey.
The food will be ready
in a minute
if you want to gather
the troops.
Yeah, sure.
Uh, do you know
where Cameron is?
Bos: No.
Hey, I just...
needed a -- a minute.
Yeah.
Bos brought some food,
so we're gonna eat soon,
if you want to join.
Oh, God.
This is too much.
[Breathes deeply]
I didn't know...
it would be this hard
to be here.
[Breathes deeply]
It's okay.
I didn't, um...
I don't mean to make this
about me.
Please,
make it about you.
I feel like everybody's
been handling me.
Nobody knows how to act.
Well, I really love it when
people say, "How are you doing?"
[Chuckles] I'm pretty sure
I asked you that.
Yeah, of course you did.
'Cause what else
are you gonna say?
And then, yeah,
how do you answer?
Hangin' in there.
That's right.
'Cause to answer honestly,
you'd have to talk incessantly
for days,
and who wants to listen
to that, right?
So...
How are you doing?
[Chuckles]
Hangin' in there.
I lost
a really good...friend.
And I don't have that many
of those to spare.
I know, like...poor me.
But I've always had
a bit of trouble
making those sorts
of connections.
[Shuddered breathing]
There's just not a lot
of people in my life.
Me neither.
Cameron:
I can't even talk to Joe.
Why not?
We're at...different places
in our life.
This has brought up
a lot of stuff for him.
Like what?
He wants kids.
Wow.
I-I'm...
If you want that,
I think you'd be great --
No, I...do not.
I mean, I just never have.
And I don't see that
changing.
Well, then don't.
It's really hard,
and I...
You have to really want it
to do a halfway decent job.
I mean...
Even then...
you always wanted it.
I mean, I...
I didn't plan on getting
pregnant right out of school,
yeah, yeah,
I-I always wanted it.
And there's nothing wrong
with not feeling that way.
Thank you.
If you change your mind,
though,
I've got a 17-year-old
I'm looking to unload, so...
[Laughs] Whatever.
I -- I miss him.
[Sighs] So do I.
♪♪
And I miss you, too.
I'm here.
♪♪
I spent so much...
I spent so much time
telling him...
everything he did wrong...
He did a ton wrong.
[Both laugh]
♪♪
[Chuckles]
[Door opens]
[Cork pops]
-Hi.
-Hey.
Something smells good.
Sure. It's an old
family recipe.
Oh, well, if anybody wants
capers in their chili,
there's about 14 jars of it
in the fridge.
How dare you.
My father'd leap out
of his grave.
[Chuckles]
-Thank you.
Saw a recipe the other day
called for pineapple in chili.
What?
Can you believe that?
Pineapple? In the --
What the hell is this country
coming to?
[Joanie and Haley
laughing upstairs]
Oh, no, thank you.
So, um...what, uh, happens next?
Who comes for all this stuff?
Uh, there's a company
that takes care
of the sale of the furniture
and things.
[Joanie and Haley laughing]
What's so funny?
It's an inside joke.
You wouldn't get it.
-Oh.
[Both laugh]
-Joe: Haley?
-Mm-hmm?
I'm sorry I couldn't get
your dad's sweater back.
That's okay.
♪♪
Joanie: Do you remember when Dad
tried to convince us
that he won a hot-dog eating
contest in Kalamazoo?
Haley: [Laughs]
That wasn't true?
Oh, honey, no.
Why would he
make that up?
I don't know.
I -- I think he thought
it was funny.
-Bos: That's hilarious.
-Dad was such a weirdo.
Hey, Joe,
can you pass the salt?
Yeah.
♪♪
Cameron: How's your room
looking, sweetheart?
Haley: Uh, it's a mess.
♪♪
Oh, God, no, Mom,
for God's sake,
do not fly back here
for this.
It's...
He'll be back soon.
No, Mo--
God, I should never
have told you.
It's not a big deal.
I think he's just under
a lot of stress, okay?
It's...
He'll be back soon.
[Joanie fusses]
Oh, I know, I know.
He'll be back soon.
He will. I know.
[Birds chirping]
♪♪
Whoo!
[Lock clicks, keys rattle]
[Donna humming]
♪♪
♪ Baby mine, dry your eyes ♪
♪ Rest your head
close to my heart ♪
♪ Never to part ♪
♪ Baby of mine ♪
[Humming]
♪♪
[Sniffles]
Don't you ever do that
to me again, okay?
I won't.
♪♪