[Indistinct conversations]
-Man: It's starting.
♪♪
What am I looking for?
Uhh...
For bootlegs...
3/4-inch socket wrench.
For the best coffee
in the city.
[Audience applauds, whistles]
-Winona Ryder. So into her.
Landscaping supplies?
-Shoes.
For the meaning of life, bra.
[Laughter]
[Speaking Spanish]
I'm looking for something funny.
[Speaking Hebrew]
I'm looking for inspiration!
I'm looking for a cure.
-I'm looking for...
I'm looking for...
Dude, the Internet.
-The Internet?
-The Internet.
What in God's name would
I look for on the Internet?
Yeah, you could...
[Applause]
...find just about anything
on the Internet.
[Inspirational music playing]
♪♪
Whoo!
[Cheers and applause]
[Cheers and applause
continue]
Okay -- it's, uh, a commercial.
And commercials exist
to sell products.
But this isn't just a product.
It isn't.
It's a new way of connecting.
A new way of being.
Uhh, hit it.
-[Gasping]
-Whoo hoo hoo!
[Cheers and applause]
So, this is the new Comet,
and it launches tonight.
No longer are we
just a way station
on people's journey
someplace else.
We are the destination.
[Cheers and applause]
This is the combined effort
of every single person here,
from our original surfers
to our coding team
headed up by Cameron Howe.
[Cheers and applause]
-Woman: Good job, Cam!
It's Cameron's last day
now that work on the relaunch
is complete...
All: Aww!
Settle down. We all knew
her days were numbered.
Uhh...
So, one more person
I'd like to mention.
A huge part of the soul
of this place is no longer here.
But this is a family business.
Comet began with Haley Clark.
Her dad and I met back in 1983.
And I told him,
"Computers aren't the thing.
They're the thing
that gets us to the thing."
And this is the...
♪♪
Com-IT! Com-IT!
All:
Com-IT! Com-IT! Com-IT!
Com-IT! Com-IT!
Whoo-ooo!
All right!
Back to it!
[Cheers and applause]
[Indistinct conversations]
Yeah, do like...
Think we can, uh,
discuss that --
-We have some mock-ups.
-Yeah, five minutes.
[Indistinct conversations]
You okay?
Yeah.
Celebrate later?
What you wanna do?
Just...get some dinner
and make out in a parked car
somewhere?
A little over-the-clothes stuff
and some dim sum.
[Laughs]
So I guess I will say
goodbye to the guys,
and uh,
I can call Alexa.
Of course. Yeah.
[Indistinct conversations]
Woman on P.A.:
Ladies at gentlemen,
at this time,
we are now boarding
our main-cabin passengers
onto Pacific Flight 590,
with nonstop service
to Bangkok.
Oh, oh. I almost forgot.
Hang on.
Here.
-What is this?
-That is a travel organizer.
I put a little map
of Bangkok in there.
-Hmm.
-Compartments for loose change
and, um, your passport,
traveler's checks.
Mom,
I'm not taking this.
Why?
Because I'm 18
and not 45.
I'm staying in hostels.
If you actually want me
to get mugged,
I'll walk around
with a Louis Vuitton wallet.
[Sighs]
Mom, this is my trip.
I just wish you'd treat me
like an adult.
Which I am, by the way.
You...
Fine.
Be safe.
Okay.
-Bye.
-Oh, my God.
Keys to my Civic
are on my desk.
Take my old
driver's license, okay?
Just in case.
It's an old photo,
but...
the cops will believe you
'cause you're a cute girl.
Maybe wear a hat
just in case.
[Laughing] Yeah.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the final
boarding call
for the Cathay Pacific
Flight 590...
Okay.
...with nonstop service
to Bangkok.
Don't go.
[Sobs]
You don't have to go.
I don't know why you have to
do this right now.
You should just...
just stay.
This is
such bullshit, Mom.
Uhh...
[Indistinct conversations]
Let's go, Mom.
[Sobbing]
[Monitor beeping, buzzing]
The doctor complains
to his wife
that she ain't so good
in bed anymore.
Well, he goes to work.
And by midday,
he calls her on the phone.
And the phone rings
and it rings...
[Beeping, buzzing]
And it rings and it rings.
And, uh, finally, she picks up.
She's out of breath.
And he goes,
"What the hell
took you so long
to answer the phone?"
[Laughs]
And she says...
Something about
a second opinion, right?
Yeah. [Clears throat]
That's the one.
So...stent looks
pretty good.
Yeah.
Any shortness of breath,
chest pains?
No. No.
Get a little light-headed
sometimes if I shit real big.
You know,
I never asked you -- Levecq --
what the hell kinda name
is that?
Levecq?
Is it, uh...Swedish?
Or...is it Norwegian,
or...
Is it a Czech--
Czechoslovakian?
Little French Canadian
there?
Hmm.
[Inhales deeply]
[Exhales]
Dutch.
You're good to go.
Well --
Okay, but -- wh--
When do you want me
to come back?
I don't.
Well, not even
for a look-see?
I mean...don't you want
to make sure
I'm not blowing a gasket?
Mm, nope.
Something goes wrong,
call.
If doesn't, don't.
[Clears throat]
You're in good health,
John.
If you take care
of yourself,
you'll live well
into the 21st century.
[Gong booms]
[Drumming]
[Aaron Copland's "Fanfare
for the Common Man" plays]
♪♪
21st century.
Son of a...
[Laughs]
♪♪
Joe: So then Marc Andreessen
and Jim Clark
fly out to Urbana Champaign,
gather all the Mosaic coders
in a pizza joint,
and offer them
$65,000 salaries,
a-a week's vacation
on his yacht in Tahiti,
and 100,000 shares
of the company.
And Clark tells them
that if they leave NCSA
and come work for him,
they'll be worth $10 million
in less than five years.
So Jim Clark steals
all the best coders
from a shitty company to go
do something way better...
Why does that sound
familiar?
Anyway, my point is that
they've all followed him
out to Silicon Valley
to build a browser,
and now Netscape is
about to demolish Mosaic.
If we were to launch Comet
inside Netscape,
it'd be slow as hell,
if it even loads correctly.
And if it doesn't, then Rover
won't or any of our competitors.
But if we can figure out
a way
to make Comet run smoothly
on Netscape,
then all of their users
will flock to us.
But those guys
created Mosaic.
They already know how
to make a browser that runs.
But they can't replicate
what they've already done.
The Mosaic code
is intellectual property.
Like the BIOS.
Yeah, like the BIOS.
And they won't know
how it works
until it's out
in the wild.
And -- And...they...
They'll want to make Netscape
better than Mosaic.
Joe...what are
we doing here?
You could've told me
all of this in bed.
Oh.
The sound card's blown.
Other than that,
it runs perfectly.
Oh...
'Kay.
I need one more thing
from you.
[Exhales deeply]
Uh-huh...
It's a quick job.
When Netscape launches,
we pull apart the code
so that Comet can load fast.
And you're bribing me
with Centipede?
Mm-hmm.
If we can pull this off,
we'll have a -- a showpiece
to offer Jim Clark so he can
promote his baby.
They will beg for us to be
a part of their infrastructure.
[Sighs] Okay.
We can't wait
until Netscape launches.
It's too late.
We have to optimize Comet
so that it's running fast
on Day One.
Which, if you want a showcase
for Jim Clark...
we need to start pulling apart
the Netscape code today.
But there's no way they're going
to just give us a working copy.
Oh, no, they won't.
Let me make a call.
I love you.
[Laughs softly]
[Distant beeping]
What is that sound?
[Beeping continues]
It's Gordon's wristwatch.
Ohh.
It would go off when he needed
to take his medication.
[Beeping continues]
I don't know where the key
to the office is.
[Beeping rapidly]
[Beeping stops]
[Scoffs] Okay.
I'll call
our locksmith today.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, do you want
to play?
Sure.
[Coins rattle]
All right.
[Buttons clicking]
[Splashing]
Oh.
Hi. [Chuckles]
How, uh --
How was Seattle?
Soggy.
[Laughs]
Sorry about the ambush.
I saw your car parked
in the driveway,
and nobody answered
when I rang the bell.
How was it?
Sending Joanie off?
Oh, you know, fine.
Just hope she stays safe.
Donna: How's Jennifer settling
in at Stanford?
Well, she was home
the first weekend.
Ohhh.
Doing laundry,
stealing food.
-Yeah.
-Last year at this time,
I couldn't bear the thought
of her leaving for college.
And now...I kinda wish she'd
at least left the zip code.
[Laughs]
Yeah, well...
[Sighs]
So...we have news.
Kimberly is pregnant.
Wh-- I--
Congratulations!
That's amazing.
Yeah.
No, but thanks.
[Laughs]
But the whole family wants to
take a big trip to Ireland
while she can still fly.
And John and I would like to do
some traveling of our own --
No, I know.
You're ready to move on.
Donna, I understand.
It's been hard.
But it's been four months.
And I need to know
what you're doing.
I'm swimming.
[Exhales sharply]
We have greased the rails.
Managing partner is yours.
Period.
You said you wanted the summer
to be with your girls.
I heard that.
But the summer is over, Donna.
The longer you wait,
the harder it's gonna get.
Trip and his stooges are
strutting through that office
every day thinking they can
run it better than you.
They think
you're getting soft.
Look, if you don't want this,
it's okay.
We can have
that conversation.
But you need to make
a decision.
[Sighs]
Okay, well...
give it some thought,
and let me know.
[Sighs]
Hm.
[Chuckles]
C--
You got to be kiddin' me.
Whaaat?
Oh, hey.
Hey, you're home
later than I thought.
How was the trip?
-It was good.
-Ahh!
Sorry, I stopped
to see Donna
on the way home
from the airport.
Well, so what's
the verdict?
We gonna sprout wings
and see the world
or is she gonna float
in that swimming pool forever?
You know, I don't know.
I'm gonna go wash
the plane off me.
All right.
Hey, what is all this stuff?
Some of Ben's old junk,
I suppose.
[Chuckles]
What have you been doing
with your bachelorhood?
Well, you know,
fartin' around.
This and that.
Went to the doctor.
Got a clean bill of health.
[Laughs]
He said I should live
well into the 21st century.
You imagine that?
Jet packs and robot overlords.
[Chuckles]
Hey, look
what I found, too.
Can you believe this?
This is a Cardiff original.
I could've packed this thing
in a box myself
when I was a teenager.
[Laughing] My God.
I bet it still works.
I just need to get
some batteries for it.
♪♪
What?
[Inhales deeply]
Honey, what?
[Clank]
What?
I'm sorry, I...
You're gonna be okay.
♪♪
Yeah, I'm okay.
I'm okay.
I'm gonna be okay.
♪♪
Ooh. Mercy.
You weren't kidding about
that plane goo, were ya?
[Laughs softly]
Come on!
Get to scrubbing!
[Chuckles]
♪♪
Ahh, look at ya.
[Indistinct talking,
phones ringing]
But how do we optimize
for Netscape
if there's no Netscape yet?
Look, I get it.
And I'm trying to figure it out.
But in the meantime, we still
have to go through --
[Knock on door]
Oh, okay. One second.
Hi.
Hi. For you.
Oh, God. Thank you.
[Laughing] Sure.
Um...
Here,
let me show you out.
So this is Comet.
Yeah.
Oh, I -- I saw
the Mercury today.
Mm.
God, the robotics thing
you're doing looks so cool.
I'm flying out with those guys
in a few weeks --
conference at the Sorbonne.
You should come.
Oh, that's [laughs] --
I mean, I find all that stuff
super fascinating,
but...it's not
really my thing.
Right?
No, I know.
But it's just a couple of days.
All expenses paid.
Worst that happens?
You meet
some fascinating people
and eat too much
lobster thermidor.
[Laughing] Yeah.
Next time.
Is what you said
last time.
Look, I know that --
I've been talking you up.
People are really interested.
And that's...great.
Hey, look, I'm sure
that it's been a tough time
for all of you.
And I get that you're trying
to help a friend out.
And I'm young, so, you know,
what do I know.
But you can get so tied up
in your obligations
you forget
your biggest obligation
is to your future self.
I know that.
Okay.
Well...
Hey, thank you.
And...
[Hushed voice] Seriously,
this is the last thing.
I hope so.
♪♪
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
♪♪
Carmen: [Laughing] But these
are, like, huge shrimps,
like, should not be called
shrimp,
and had those, like, little
feeler touchy things
still attached?
-No!
-Yes!
-No.
Huge plate, deep-fried,
and those...feeler things
were, like, this long.
-Come on.
-Oh, no.
Please tell me
you didn't eat one.
It was a business dinner.
[Laughing] I had to.
So I took a glug of saké,
picked one up, and just...
[Crunches]
[Slurps]
-Oh, good lord.
You're disgusting.
That's my story.
-[Laughs]
Okay, Joe, you're up.
Yeah. Uhh...
Porpoise testicles.
-Joe...
-Ughh.
...you did not eat porpoise
testicles. [Laughs]
I 100% did.
It is not legal to even eat
any porpoise anything.
I ate those fishy balls.
I did.
Do porpoises even have
testicles?
I think so.
I mean, what is a porpoise?
I mean, yeah.
I think it was a porpoise.
But whatever it was, it was --
it was squishy,
and I vomited...
-Mm!
...into the gutter,
and...Donna, you're up.
Oh. Uhh...
Yeah. All right --
beef carpaccio.
Ugh. So weird.
Um...
Um, Cameron will do
this thing
where she can, uh, like,
set up, uh...
What?
...an assembly line
of bologna, mayonnaise...
-Ohh!
-...and pickles.
No, not pickles --
cornichon.
And, yes, duh...
-I'm corrected.
it's delicious.
You get a pile of mayonnaise,
pile of cornichon,
dip the cornichon
in the mayonnaise,
wrap it in bologna,
pop it in your mouth.
[Laughs softly]
That's pretty gross.
So have you guys heard
from Joanie?
Yeah.
Uh, she went
to the Grand Palace,
and she saw this huge
elephant park
and something called
the Sanctuary of Truth,
which is this massive temple
carved totally out of wood.
And on her second night,
there was this monsoon?
But it's not like here,
the rain was super warm,
so she went running
through the streets
and she got all soaked
and she ended up eating noodles
in this little shack
and made friends
with these total strangers,
and now they're all backpacking
to Phuket.
Wow. That's awesome.
Yeah, I know.
It's like...
She decides she wants
to do something,
and she just does it,
you know?
Where's she going next?
I don't know.
Uh, I don't know.
I, uh, didn't get a chance
to talk to her when she called.
She just spoke to Haley, so...
Oh.
Uh...
Hey, Haley. There's something
I want to show you.
Hm?
Come with me.
Yeah, go check
it out.
-Okay.
-We'll clean up.
It's the commercial.
I've just been dying
to show it to you.
Oh...no,
that's -- that's okay.
No, you got to see this.
Come on.
We got to grab lunch soon.
Catch up, you know?
Yeah, sure.
[Faucet running]
-Ooh!
[Faucet stops]
[Hushed voice] Sorry.
We're not actually
gonna do the dishes.
Um, Joe likes the dishes done
in a very particular way,
and I'm not good at doing them
like that,
so I just don't do them
anymore.
[Comet commercial playing]
Hey, so you're
the new Diane now.
Oh...Yeah, no.
I mean, nothing's official yet.
I'm still trying to decide
if I even want it.
What?
Of course you want it.
Yeah, you know, it's just,
I'm already so far removed from
the creative side of things.
And it only gets worse if you're
managing partner, you know?
Oh, uh, how are things
with Alexa?
Are you, uh, you working on
something new?
Kinda. Yeah.
[Wine flowing]
God, she just scored
with this --
Oh, yeah,
the robotics thing.
Robotics, yeah, yeah, yeah.
The Mercury...
Yeah.
Ugh. God, I miss that.
Doing things.
Yeah.
I mean, it's not like
she actually did anything.
She just found
those people, you know?
She doesn't really get
her hands dirty.
Ah.
Why, do you want to do
something?
No.
I don't know.
Aaaghh...I just --
I haven't had an original idea
in kind of a long time.
Well, you came up with
Community. [Laughs softly]
That was just an idea
that percolated down
from one of your ideas.
That's not totally
accurate.
And, anyway, ideas
are, like, not the work.
Yeah.
I mean, what you do --
it's more than just
signing a check.
I-I get that now.
[Laughs softly]
So I'm not parasite?
You're not a parasite.
[Laughs softly]
♪♪
What the hell.
Hey, hold on.
Haley, wait.
Is it because...
It's weird to see him.
Is it weird?
Yeah, it's weird to see my dead
dad in a stupid commercial.
It's weird that I'm in it,
and that you didn't even ask me,
and I don't even look
like that anymore.
And it's weird that you've taken
this thing that I made,
and -- and now it's yours.
And all you want is
to make money off of it!
Hey, I understa--
I'm 15!
I don't want to have lunch
and catch up or whatever.
I don't want to be
at dinners.
I want everyone
to leave me alone.
[Keys jangling]
I'll be in the car.
[Door opens, slams shuts]
♪♪
Uhh...
I'm pulling the ad.
Joe...
Look, you put a lot of money
in that commercial.
Don't just throw it
down the drain.
Maybe you can
cut her out of it.
It's my company.
I'm gonna do some work.
Before bed.
[Pots clank]
What work?
Uhh, I've...been putting things
off with Alexa.
And, uh...I need to give that
some thought.
[Microwave humming]
I gave Joe permission, you know,
for you to be in the ad.
So if you want to be angry,
you should be angry with me.
It's not his fault.
[Plastic crackling]
I thought you'd like it.
I just want
some Bagel Bites.
Haley, if there's anything you
want to talk about, I'm --
[Microwave beeping]
[Sighs]
[Plate clinks]
Hey, I know we said
I'd go back to work
as soon as you started
back up at school,
but if you want,
I can stay home --
No. I want you
to go back to work.
And I want you to stop
worrying about me so much.
Just, you know,
worry about you.
You're here all day.
Swimming.
Well, I like swimming.
Yeah, Mom, I like swimming, too,
but Jesus Christ.
[Laughs]
Not bad.
They're incredible.
Um...I'm gonna go
to my room.
So...Night.
John:
Oh, that is a beaut, huh?
Donna: Uh-huh.
Ooh.
That's good cocoa.
Mama used to make it
with real chocolate.
She'd put it in the double
boiler and melt it down.
That instant bullshit
they have.
Ugh, ugh.
It's alkalized cocoa powder,
what it is.
That's the garbage
that's left over
after they roast
the cocoa beans,
and they run it
through a chemical bath
so you can't taste
how awful it is.
My God, it's a national
travesty.
Yeah, well...
things used to be
more real, right?
See the way they worked --
this connects to this.
Now it's just
all on a chip.
Yeah,
it's like magic now.
Ahh, yeah, well...
not my kind of magic.
[Chuckles]
What's so special you need to
get this thing fixed today, huh?
You gonna miss the Glenn Miller
Orchestra or something?
No, just got
a bug up my butt,
wanted to see
if it still worked.
I used to pack that exact model
into boxes
all day
at the Cardiff factory.
[Chuckles]
[Laughing] Yeah.
Yeah.
I can still smell
that place.
It's weird, isn't it,
how much stuff you remember
from early in life?
And how all that stuff
in the middle just kinda...
just kinda runs together.
I am seven years older than
my father was when he died.
He spent the whole day
before
yelling about how the tree
from the Malone place
was gonna bore
into that sewer line
and cost him
a damn fortune.
[Chuckles]
And then boom, down.
Just...spent his last day
bitching about tree roots.
Oh, Dad.
Anyway, it just seems to me
if you want something,
best to go get it done.
Now.
ANNOUNCER: It's a real pitchers'
duel here.
-Hey!
-[Laughs softly]
Now, that's magic.
See?
Perfect.
[Static]
Hey, would you, uh...
Would you have Diane
give me a call?
Will do.
Ahh, screw it.
[Exhales deeply]
Just tell her I'm ready.
Okay.
[Veruca Salt's "Seether"
playing, volume increasing ]
♪ I try to knock her out ♪
♪ I try to cram her
back in my mouth, yeah ♪
♪♪
♪ Can't fight the seether ♪
♪ Seether ♪
♪ I can't see her till
I'm foaming at the mouth ♪
[Music stops]
[Imitates monkey
screeching]
[Laughs]
[Indistinct conversations]
Hey.
Hey...um...
So, I was thinking.
I have my sister's car.
Because remember how I said
she's going to Thailand?
Which she says
is hella badass.
Um...and, I mean,
I'm sure you have a car, too,
and I'm not even supposed to be
driving it yet,
but...whatever.
So, um, I was --
I was wondering, um,
have you h-- have you heard of
"Natural Born Killers"?
Yes.
Yeah.
Juliette Lewis is awesome,
and it's playing
at the Century 24,
but it's super popular
so it might be sold out...
-Oh, well, that's --
-But if it is, uh,
then we could go to
the Winchester Mystery House
which is right next door,
and they do
these midnight tours.
Which are dope,
I think...
-[Laughs softly]
-And, um, yeah.
Anyway, um [inhales deeply]
could I take you to see
"Natural Born Killers"?
[Door bells jingle]
Um...
[Inhales sharply]
[Whimpers]
[Sobbing]
♪ ...long time ago, baby ♪
[Broom sweeping]
Okay, hold on.
Hold -- almost.
♪ I am nobody's friend ♪
All right.
Okay.
[Gasps]
It's truly a masterpiece.
Yeah.
[Both laugh]
This is
your Sistine Chapel.
Awww, hell.
I found a box of Miracle-Gro
down there from 1982.
[Chuckles]
All right.
I'm done.
Done, I say.
[Sighs]
How about you and I
do some actual living?
Hm?
[Paul and Paula's "Hey Paula"
plays ]
♪ Hey, hey, Paula,
I wanna marry you ♪
no one else could ever do ♪
♪ I've waited so long
for school to be through ♪
♪ Paula, I can't wait
no more for you ♪
[Laughs]
♪ My love, my love ♪
[Keyboard clacking]
Can't we cheat it?
Make it so we that we store
recurrent Comet images
in the user's
Netscape cache?
It would make it load
so much faster.
Yeah, I would,
if Netscape supported that,
but they don't, so...
Is the query box fixed?
Or does it still get
a null response
if you put a space
before the carriage return?
Still on my punch list.
[Foot taps]
Joe, this is still
an early beta.
So there's tons of bugs.
We don't know what
they're gonna fix,
how they're gonna fix it, how
those fixes are gonna affect us.
Guess I should
just shut up.
No, but could
you just relax?
We've got tons of time.
We've got two days.
Yeah, we have two days.
Okay, here.
That looks worse
than it did before.
I know. It's part of
the...process.
[Inhales deeply,
exhales]
Maybe you shouldn't watch
how the sausage is made.
[Notebook slams]
[Pen slams]
[Computer dings]
Are you checking
your e-mail?
What?
Nothing.
No, what?
What, am I not taking this
seriously enough for you?
I didn't say that.
You didn't have to say it.
You're acting like it.
We've got the cheat sheet
to the exam.
We've won.
I just don't want to miss
another opportunity.
Two days.
Two days. That's all
I'm asking for.
Can you just focus
long enough
for us to get Comet
optimized...
Oh, my God.
...so that it loads perfectly
when Netscape ships.
I'm giving you
my focus.
Jesus,
I'm doing you a favor.
Who's the e-mail from?
[Scoffing] Are you...
Alexa.
Go ahead.
Read it.
[Sighs]
Oh, g--
It's the new beta.
Shall I thank her for you,
or do you want to compose
something
that'll make her feel
like a total shitbag
for helping you out?
Give me a break.
[Computer chimes]
Okay.
Looks the same
as the old one.
Yeah, the skin's the same.
Let's see how she runs.
-Whoa.
-Uhh...
That's way faster
than I thought.
-Yeah.
-Wow.
Hold on.
What, you can put text in fields
before the page fully loads?
Really nice touch.
Okay, so they've got
support for JPEG.
The formatting is perfect.
I'm gonna set a call
with Jim Clark.
[Gasps] You know
what we could do?
We could put a badge
on our homepage
saying
"Optimized for Netscape."
And the gifs would render
smoothly if --
Wait, wait...
What is that?
That wasn't there before.
What the hell is Yahoo?
Two guys. Stanford.
Used to be called
"Jerry and David's Guide
to the World Wide Web."
[Laughing] But...
This sucks.
The design's terrible,
there's no image support,
they're --
On the toolbar.
What?
They're on the toolbar.
That's it.
They've won.
They're the directory
to the Web.
We don't exist.
[Watch beeping]
Oh, God.
Come on.
[Beeping continues]
Joe.
Joe!
[Beeping continues]
[Beeping quickens]
[Beeping stops]
♪♪
[Whimpers]
There's coffee.
I'm all right.
[Exhales deeply]
I wanted it to work.
I wanted us to work.
Yeah?
Me too.
It did.
For a while.
Yeah.
♪♪
The thing that gets you
to the thing.
Huh?
♪♪
It was you.
It was always you.
♪♪
[Elevator bell dings]
[Exhales deeply]
[Elevator dings, descends]
♪♪
[Applause]
Thank you.
Thank you all.
Let's, uh, get right down to it,
shall we?
♪♪
[Indistinct conversation]
Hi.
Glad you reconsidered.
Mm-hmm.
I'm just going
for the lobster thermidor.
Mm.
♪♪
Trip: ...and to circle back
to Web search,
I got word that when Netscape
launches this week,
Yahoo will be the default
directory.
Got their own button
and everything.
So Comet
is pretty much kaput.
And --
Uh-- so, where does
that leave Rover?
Should off-load it for parts,
sell it on the B2B market.
Lucky for us,
it's algorithm-based,
so it actually has
some value.
There's a --
What is it, Benji? It's a...
medical indexing company
that's actually expressed
some interest, so...
We should probably
look into that one
and try to get 20% to 30%
of value and --
Hey, go back.
What is Netscape's search
directory called?
It's, uh...Yahoo?
[Scoffs]
I'm sorry, what is it?
It's "Yahoo"?
Ya-hoo?
Yeah, Yahoo.
Like, "Yahoo," with a...
with an exclamation point.
Oh, Yahoo with an exclamation
point, not a question mark?
'Cause you keep saying Yahoo
with a question mark,
so I was...
-Okay.
Shouldn't it be more
like...Yahoo!
[Chuckles]
Sure.
Come on. [Laughs]
Drill down
with me now, Trip.
Yahoo!
Yahoo.
[Laughing] No, man!
No!
[Laughing]
Oh, Jesus!
Now put some mustard on it,
you know?!
Yahoo!
There!
Ya-hooooooooo!
[Laughing]
That's so...
[Laughing continues]
♪♪