Ross: Everybody needs a friend,
even an old tree.
Okay, now,
take our liner brush.
Paint thinner.
Want to thin it down.
Thin some brown down,
very, very thin.
Very thin.
A lot of paint thinner.
Let's put
a little arm or two.
Maybe this old tree
don't have any leaves.
[Mumbles]
Maybe he's already retired
for the -- for the year.
[Telephone ringing]
[Sighs]
[Ringing continues]
[Exhales sharply]
[Telephone beeps]
Hello?
Joanie: Hey, it's me.
Hey. What's going on?
I-Is everything okay?
Can I just
tell you something?
Uh, yeah,
o-of course you can.
[Exhales sharply]
Okay, so there's
this German guy in the hostel
named Otto.
Oh, yeah? Is he cute?
Anyway...
he was telling me about
this ancient temple ruin.
Actually, he was going
on and on about it
at 3:30 in the morning
while I was trying to sleep
and I wanted
to bash his head in
with my
"Lonely Planet" guide.
But it sounded
kind of awesome.
This, uh --
the temple ruin?
Yeah, it was burned
to the ground by raiders
like 100 years ago.
I asked Otto
if I could go with him,
and he said yes.
This place was wild, empty.
It was a major shrine city.
Okay, anyway,
Aat, our guide,
he brought us to this tree,
and it had this --
this sandstone head
of the Buddha in it.
And the roots of the tree
had completely grown around it
and covered everything
except its face.
And...
Aat had us get on our --
our hands and our knees
as we got closer to it
because you can't look down
at the Buddha.
You have to be respectful,
so we crawled up to it,
and, um, I reached out
and I-I touched the roots,
and Aat put his forehead
to the ground...
so we did, too.
And it's not like we were
worshipping the Buddha
or the statue,
you know?
It was, like...
more of the tree...
for what it was doing,
and...
burned stones and grass.
♪♪
Anyway,
it, um, started to rain.
And when I put my forehead
to the mud,
I thought about Dad...
[Sighs]
...like he was still
with me,
Just in, like,
a different way.
♪♪
Oh, honey, that's beautiful.
It's pretty cool.
[Chuckles]
♪♪
I think maybe you and I
were actually pretty similar,
and maybe that's why
we fight all the time,
you know?
[Chuckles]
Yeah, yeah.
I do.
[Phone beeping]
Oh, shit, my calling card
is running out.
I love you, Mom! Bye!
[Receiver clicks]
[Chuckles]
[Phone beeps]
Ross: There.
Shoot, I think with that,
we about have
a finished painting.
Good luck.
Good luck, Mikey.
Thanks, Joe.
Yeah.
Thank you.
No, really.
Comet was...a miracle.
Wish we could've
done it longer.
You made the right call.
Like you said,
it would've been a bummer
to sit around here
and watch the world
swallow us up.
Thanks.
♪♪
I like this place.
I know it doesn't
feel like it now,
but this is
the start of something.
♪♪
[Sighs heavily]
[Birds chirping]
[Indistinct conversations
on TV]
Mmm.
-But now...
-Yeah! Now!
Woman: Oh, my goodness.
I have get ready fast.
[Both laugh]
[Bell rings]
Mm.
Oh.
I'm sorry, are you --
are you open?
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
[Muffled] Wait.
[Clears throat]
Osiris!
Turn down the tube, babe.
Well, sit down.
Denise: Please, have a seat.
Okay, so it's gonna be, uh,
$20 for a palm reading
and $30
for palm and cards.
Um...
Thank you.
May I see your palm,
please?
Oh, yikes, I'm sorry.
Mm, but your salsa line
looks pretty good, huh?
[Napkins rustling]
Mm. Sorry.
Long life line.
Oh, um...
broken here and there.
Lot of challenges.
Changes.
Challenges and changes,
huh?
Shocking.
What's that?
Mm.
Test for stubbornness.
Hmm. Sharp head line.
Smart.
Successful.
Little...selfish maybe?
Heart line seems to say...
some love.
Some loss.
Come on, Denise,
enough softballs.
Why'd you come in here
today?
Destiny.
Dessert now?
Dessert?
You just scarfed down
those nachos!
[Laughs]
How many?
Two.
Just two?
Okay. Have fun.
That -- That's my grandson,
Osiris.
Thanks for your time.
Wait, don't you want
your card reading?
You paid for it.
Would you please put
your right hand on the deck?
[Sighs]
Hmm.
Okay. Thank you.
[Cards shuffling]
Past.
Present.
Future.
What does that mean?
Well, you know,
they really mean
whatever you want them
to mean.
Well, you know,...
destruction.
Destruction?
Yeah.
Commonly.
Agony, indecision, misery.
[Chuckling] Christ.
[Laughs]
So I lose again?
Okay, great.
No. Not necessarily.
Because, you see,
this golden horizon
behind the storm clouds,
that could be something.
Can I keep this?
Sure.
I sell packs
for another $20.
[Birds chirping]
[Car engine revs in distance]
[Tires screech]
Man: Jesus! You okay?
[Tires squeal]
Joe MacMillan?
Dale: And like that,
we're getting killed
in the PC business.
Who'd have guessed,
right?
Joe: Me.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs] Of course.
Besides you.
[Uncle Tupelo's "New Madrid"
plays in background]
Can I just say, Joe,
it's been a kick
watching you carve a path
all these years.
Always on the bleeding edge.
I mean, way out there.
Just,
more than a few of us
really grew to trust
your finger in the air.
♪ Mr. Browning
has a prediction ♪
♪♪
Have the leaves changed yet?
What?
Back east.
Oh, uh, yeah.
Just started.
Gorgeous.
All right,
better get to SFO.
They got us flying
business class now.
Believe it?
No, please, I got it.
♪♪
Can't wait to see
what you do next, Joe.
♪ Walk with me
to the fountain ♪
♪♪
♪ And hold ♪
♪ Onto my arm ♪
♪♪
[Beck's "Beercan" plays]
♪ Alcohol on my hands ♪
♪ I got plans to ditch myself
and get outside ♪
♪ Dancing women
throwing plates ♪
♪ Decapitating
their laughing dates ♪
♪ Swirling chickens
caught in flight ♪
♪ Out of focus,
much too bright ♪
♪ Coming down, shiny teeth ♪
♪ Game shows suckers
trying to bleed ♪
♪ But I got a drug
and I got the bug ♪
Impressed?
♪ And I got something
better than love ♪
When will we move in?
-[Laughs] Right now.
-Donna is on speed dial.
I think we're gonna
have you guys set up here.
♪ How you like me now? ♪
Okay, great.
♪ Pretty good ♪
Thank you so much
for having us.
♪ Going on, feeling strong ♪
I'm so excited to be here.
Don't thank me.
♪ I quit my job
blowing leaves ♪
♪ Telephone bills
up my sleeves ♪
♪ Choking like
a one man dust bowl ♪
Man: Yes.
♪ Freedom rock slime ball,
talking in code ♪
♪ We went down ♪
♪ Lit up the shack ♪
♪ Grab me a beer
out of the sack ♪
♪ Everybody bent over twice ♪
Okay,
so we've got this here.
♪ Painting the walls,
throwing some dice ♪
Man: That's so common.
♪ Leaping up into the air ♪
There's, like,
buttons on the side.
♪ Getting juiced up
beyond belief ♪
No, no, no, John.
No, I'm gonna --
No, I'm telling you,
you got to --
I'm trying to do that.
Uh, that was John.
Let me try.
No, no, I want to --
Let me just try it.
Let me at least try.
♪ And they were singing
like this ♪
Look, look, look.
♪ Winos throwing Frisbees
at the sun ♪
♪ Put my soul between a bun ♪
♪ Now I'm hungry,
now I'm drunk ♪
Where you guys going?
We got tacos.
♪ Now I'm running like
a flaming pig ♪
Taco time, you guys!
Come and get 'em.
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
Good.
♪ Scraping off the attitude ♪
Oh, wow, what is this?
What are we looking at?
♪ Old man eating all my food ♪
♪ Don't be kind,
don't be rude ♪
So, this is
one tenth of 1%
of one little gene,
but this...
♪ Just shake your boots
and let it all get loose ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ My goodness ♪
♪♪
[Inhaling sharply]
[Coughs]
Are you all right?
Oh, yeah.
That nasal gel
you gave me on the plane,
it feels like a slug
crawled into my nose
and took a dump.
Well, you'll thank me
when you don't get sick.
How will I thank you
for something
that doesn't happen?
It would be neat
to hear you
thank somebody
for something.
[Scoffs]
Two months abroad
with top investors,
and we've got
nothing to show for it.
Yeah, well, it's tough
for the work to translate
once we got north of Oslo.
Well, the point was
to get you in good
with some real
European players.
Players?
My God, I couldn't tell you
what any of those people did
save for go out to dinner
at fancy restaurants
and name drop.
How much did this trip
even cost?
Well, it's my money,
and I'm spending it
to help you bring
your ideas to fruition.
Okay.
But if you're just
gonna sit there
and cut everyone down like
some sardonic asshole --
I'm sorry.
I didn't perform
well enough for you.
I'm not your monkey.
Look, I know that
you're still dealing
with some
personal issues.
Or...maybe...
you're just losing interest
because now's
the part of the process
you actually
have to do some work
and not just bullshit
about the possibilities.
Can you pull over here?
Cameron.
[Car door opens]
Cameron!
[Car door slams]
Bosworth:
How did you even get home?
Cameron: Oh, just walked a mile
to the McDonald's,
used their phone to call a cab,
cab cost $200.
You should've
called me at home.
I love me some McDonald's --
them little apple pies.
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Delis-cous.
So, have you talked since?
Two weeks.
Just radio silence.
Oh, no.
So I think that's done.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
You know, there's this thing
in CompSci I remember --
recursion.
Where a specific function
calls upon itself repeatedly
within a program.
So in order
to solve the big problem,
it uses the same small problem
over and over
as the solution to increasingly
complex issues.
And that, my friend,
is how my software runs.
[Chuckles]
Sorry about Joe,
by the way.
Thanks.
I actually still have
some stuff of his
to give back,
but I just can't
bear the thought
of seeing him right now,
you know?
Can I tell you
something?
Yeah?
You got a lot of love
in you.
More than anybody
I ever met.
It's bursting out of you.
You're taking the world
in these -- in these big gulps,
and you can't help
but to let yourself
get drowned in it.
Overwhelms you,
makes you live like
you're ready to explode
at any minute.
They don't see it.
I do.
It's a burden you carry.
[Sighs]
You don't think
I'm just running away again?
[Scoffs]
Oh, I -- you might be.
I'm thinking about Florida.
Florida?
What the hell's in Florida?
They got alligators
and that dadgum Epcot Center?
What?
My mom.
Ah.
Man, I'm just tired of
saying goodbye, you know?
Recursion.
Exactly.
Maybe you ought to have yourself
a heart attack.
Yeah?
Yeah, yeah.
[Chuckling] Sure.
[Sighs]
You know, when I went down,
I did everything I could
to stay in the ring.
Fought like hell.
Had this mantra in my head.
"Just stay in it,
stay in it, stay in it."
But I was losing.
I knew at that moment
if I didn't give up,
that guy's gonna kill me.
[Sighs]
I...
I got nothing left
to give up.
Oh...
I know it's --
If you stay, it's hard.
If you leave, it's hard.
It's all hard.
It's --
♪♪
Sometimes it's not even about
what you want.
It's about
what it wants for you.
All you can do is...
listen and see if
you can hear what it's saying.
It's saying goodbye.
[Sighs]
But, yeah,
hit the road, then.
[Sighs heavily]
[Chuckles]
I don't want to say goodbye
to you.
Well, hell, sweetheart,
it better not be forever.
♪♪
[Sighs]
I fully expect you
to come back
and shake me all up again.
♪♪
Don't let me get old.
[Chuckles]
♪♪
[Knocks on door]
You my 11:30?
No.
Have a look around.
[Footsteps in distance,
indistinct conversations]
♪♪
Nancy: [In distance]
Vaulted ceilings,
crown molding,
great neighborhood.
♪♪
What happened
to the previous tenant?
Not sure,
but this has been on the market
something like
15 days now.
♪♪
[Tapping]
Are you sure
it's okay out there?
Donna: Oh, uh, yeah.
I mean,
they'll go around.
Okay.
[Rattles]
So, I'm, uh,
your last stop, huh?
You are.
I went by Joe's
this morning.
He's totally gone.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, I didn't, uh --
the real estate agent told me
it'd been empty for weeks.
He didn't...
I'm sorry, I guess I just
thought he would call.
Oh, God, Joe.
Yeah, he, uh, came by here
and said he was leaving
and that he'd be in touch.
Uh, Haley got a letter from him
a couple days ago.
A letter?
Wow, well, I guess we're both
fond of rash departures.
Oh, hey, um, could you just
bring me one more of those,
and I think we'll be fine.
Donna, sorry,
I'm gonna finish this.
I didn't...[scoffs]
...mean to just burst in on you
and the thing you're doing.
No. No, no, no.
Please, it's not...
Donna: [Sighs]
Hey, why don't you stay
for this thing tonight?
I think you might
really dig it.
Yeah?
Think I'm a little
below dress code.
Oh, come on.
You can just borrow
something of mine.
No, thank you.
I really appreciate it.
I just -- I wanted to be
in Carson City
come nightfall, so...
Yeah, no, that makes sense,
I guess.
Man: Sorry.
Hey.
Aah! God. Oh. Sorry.
I am sorry.
No, no, it's fine.
It's hardwood.
Hey, look, I --
I wish we could've
hung out more
these last couple months.
Yeah, I know.
Me too.
It's just work
has been crazy, and...
Well, you know,
probably we'll end up
seeing each other more
now that I'm gone,
'cause I'll come into town,
and we'll really
make a point of it.
Yeah, and you'll be back
seeing Alexa, I'm sure,
and...
No.
[Chuckles]
That's, uh -- That's dead.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You know, some things just
aren't the right fit.
Hey, Mom.
Hi.
Hey.
Uh, this is my boyfriend,
Kevin.
'Sup?
Oh.
Haley, uh,
Cameron is moving, I guess.
What?
Yeah, I, uh --
I'm going on a road trip,
and we'll see, uh,
where I -- I end up.
Haley: Cool.
So everyone's leaving now.
Bye, I guess.
Uh...
Sorry, uh --
Boyfriend?
Yeah.
[Door closes]
You okay
with the door closed?
Oh, yeah, completely.
She just
works on her computer,
and he does
the hackey sack.
That sounds right.
You know, I get the sense
that she doesn't even
really like him.
Yeah.
Oh, she's doing these
college-level C++ classes.
It's one night a week
at Foothill,
and she's been just
killing herself
over this project,
but she loves it.
Can you believe it?
I can believe it.
Okay, I'm gonna go, uh,
and throw this tomato out.
Oh, God,
I'm sorry I didn't take that.
No, here,
the trash is...
Where?
Hey, I'm...
[Scoffs]
Drive safe, okay?
I'm, uh --
I'm gonna miss you.
[Sighs]
[Chuckles]
Donna, this is --
[Haley screams]
Donna: Haley?
What happened?
Haley: I can't open
the work file.
I keep trying to open it,
and it says
"Drive not ready."
Ugh, did you hit it
with your sack?
What?
Hackey, Kev.
Uh, no, I've just been
chilling here.
That's my
semester project!
-Okay.
-Hang on.
All right, try it again.
[Computer beeping]
It's the same error message.
Yeah, the platter's
not spinning.
[Screams]
I hate these stupid things!
Breathe. Kevin,
do you have any money?
I've got 20 bucks
from delivering
Thanksgiving turkeys
to old people.
Okay, great,
could you do me a favor
and just take her to a movie
or something?
No, I have to do this.
I know.
"Star Trek: Generations"
is out.
Okay, fine.
Okay.
[Chuckles] Stop.
Donna: Oh, yeah.
Yeah, the head's
stuck to the platter.
If I can get it off
and parked,
we'll have
to check the data.
Well, as long as it boots,
I can go through
the contents.
Sorry about this.
I know you wanted
to get driving.
No. No, [Scoffs]
It's not like I'm desperate
to see Carson City.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
[Squeaks]
Oy, that didn't
sound pretty.
But, hey,
there we go.
Oh, God,
I got to go get ready.
Can you keep going
with this?
Yeah, yeah.
[Keyboard clacking]
How's it going in here?
-Jesus.
-What?
No, you just -- you...
you just do that
so well.
[Laughs]
Oh. Hey, yeah.
One of the benefits
of throwing
a fancy cocktail thing.
So?
Well,
the file's damaged.
I'm trying to figure out
if I can get a side way in
to recover the data.
Well, I hope we can save
some of it.
So, what,
do you just kick it?
Hmm?
Yeah, you just --
just kick it to yourself.
How do you win?
You just -- just use
your knees and stuff.
I don't get it.
You know it really
pisses me off,
that Joe would just leave
like that.
Things fell apart, yeah,
but for him
to just up and...
Whatever.
It didn't work.
Nothing here did, so...
[Sighs]
And I'm sorry
that I didn't tell you
I was leaving sooner.
I just [sighs] --
I just wanted
to make a decision
and not have somebody
talk me out of it.
Hey, if it's what
you want to do,
it's what you want to do.
[Keyboard clacking]
Yeah, man.
If you do
what you always did,
you're gonna get
what you always got.
If the elevator's broken,
take the stairs.
It works if you work it.
Unless it's more and more
of what doesn't work.
Meetings?
[Sighs] Oh...
A few.
You?
My mom.
I might see her
on this trip.
That's good.
Cameron: [Scoffs]
Man, this might be toast.
Donna:
You did copy the file
before you converted it
to rich text, right?
Yeah, but I skipped RTF
and went straight
to the hex editor.
Rebuild the header, too,
and check the permissions.
Even if there's
version control?
You want to recover data
or you want to make
a 15-year-old cry again?
[Chuckles] Okay.
[Keyboard clacking]
Hey.
What if we worked together
again?
Um...
What do you, um --
Do you have an idea?
No,
the idea can come later.
That's not
what's important.
I'm sorry.
That, um --
Oh, God, yeah.
That -- I --
No. No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
Please, forget I said it.
I'm sorry.
I -- I don't know
what I was thinking.
Cameron.
Sorry.
♪♪
[Sighs]
Uh...
I'm gonna go
check on the caterers.
I'll be back.
Okay, yeah,
I'll keep working on this.
♪♪
[Sighs]
[Door closes]
♪♪
[Neil Young's "Harvest Moon"
plays in background]
Diane: So, imagine
there are five of us
crammed into
this rented Land Rover,
and Kimberly already
has morning sickness.
Oh.
And the Irish roads
are built for,
I don't know,
horse-drawn carriages.
John --
John stops
and takes a picture
of every shamrock we see.
Every (no audio) shamrock.
[Laughs]
[Sighs]
And more importantly,
what you have done
with the firm
over the past
three months...
Mm.
...wow.
Thank you.
That really means a lot.
♪ Just like children sleepin' ♪
♪ We could dream
this night away ♪
Cameron's here.
I thought she'd be halfway
across the country by now.
Yeah, me too.
That was the plan.
But she, um...
She just floated the idea
of working with me again
just out of nowhere.
With one foot out the door
and the rest of her life
packed in a silver tube?
♪♪
Yeah, well,
that is her gift.
Thinking of
impossible things.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ We know where
the music's playin' ♪
[Sighs]
[In distance] ♪ Let's go out
and feel the night ♪
Any luck?
Okay.
How was the movie?
It was weird.
Kirk was stuck
in this, like,
frozen time ribbon thing
and he was
repeatedly living
the happiest part of his life
for decades.
And then Picard comes
and he's like,
"Dude, get out of the ribbon.
You got to help me."
And so Kirk is like, "Sure,"
and he does,
and he, like,
immediately dies.
Picard's a jerk.
[Chuckles]
Where's the Kevinator?
Mm...
He's probably wolfing down
all the tuna tartare
like a dumb barracuda.
[Sighs]
♪ When we were strangers ♪
♪ I watched you from afar ♪
Did Joe write you
a letter?
Yeah. Why?
Um, it was just to me.
Yeah, you're right.
Sorry.
Did you love him?
[Sighs]
Yeah.
I did.
♪♪
Um, I'll just, like --
I'll just summarize.
♪♪
Uh...
He said he, like,
needs to start over,
and that he didn't air
the Comet commercial
because, you know, um...
He talked about UNC
putting their radio station
on the Internet.
[Chuckles]
What?
Oh, it's an inside joke.
You wouldn't get it.
Yeah.
Um, he said that
my dad was proud of me
and that
if he was ever in town,
he'd come and see us.
Um...
And he said
not to forget him,
even when I'm running
all of Silicon Valley.
♪♪
He's joking again.
Yeah, Armonk,
where is that?
♪♪
Um, it's where he's from.
It's where, uh, IBM is.
Mm.
♪♪
[Sighs]
Hey, I'm sorry that
we couldn't recover your data.
It's fine.
Like what Joe said.
What's that?
Fresh start.
[Inhales sharply]
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Well...
Come find me
in the time ribbon.
I will.
♪♪
Yes, good.
[Laughs]
If you'll excuse me
one second.
I'm just gonna --
[Indistinct conversations]
Uh, thank you.
Um, I just, uh --
I wanted to thank you guys
for coming out tonight.
[Chuckles]
"You guys."
See what we're up against?
[Laughter]
When I graduated
from Berkeley in '75
with a degree
in computer science,
nobody batted an eye.
That's probably because
back then,
coders were like
secretaries and engineers,
meaning little solder soldiers
on the assembly lines,
were kind of invisible.
And we're used to that.
But somewhere along the line,
these jobs became important.
And don't get me wrong,
I'm happy to hang out
with "you guys" any time
and eat good food,
but I hope that by the time
my daughters are my age
that they don't have to have
gatherings like this anymore
to remind themselves
that they're actually here.
I've been in tech
for 18 years.
I've won.
And I've lost.
I am a woman
who voted her female partner
out of her own company,
the company she founded.
I am a woman
who lost a marriage
to, among other things,
this line of work.
I can't sleep at night
sometimes
worrying if
I'm seeing my kids enough
or if I've been there
enough for them
or if it's already
too late.
But...
...I've done things.
That always comes with a price,
but I did them.
One of the many things
I've learned
is that no matter what you do,
somebody is around
the next corner
with a better version of it,
and if that person is a man,
it might not even be better.
It just might get
more attention.
And sometimes,
that person is you.
The you that's never satisfied
with what you just did
because you're obsessed
with whatever is next.
The one constant is this.
It's you, it's us.
The project
gets us to the people.
♪♪
Because it's people
that got me where I am,
people like Diane Gould.
People like my husband
and my first partner,
Gordon Clark.
People like my last
and best partner, Cameron Howe.
♪♪
And for all the rest of you,
I hope that tonight can be
the beginning of something,
something so that
even if we see each other
across the corporate
battle lines one day,
that you will know
that I am rooting for you.
I can't help but not.
Because I am a partner by trade
and a mother and a sister
by design.
And I am --
I am so proud to be
on this journey with you.
[Applause]
[Exhales sharply]
Aah!
Donna: Oh, my God!
Oh!
No, this is good.
Now everyone knows
you were the crazy one.
Oh, good.
Well, I'm glad I could be
of some service.
Donna: [Chuckles]
So...
About working together.
[Sighs] I'm sorry.
It was a terrible idea.
I shouldn't have
brought it up.
I can't tell you
what it means to me
that you asked.
I think in some ways, I...
probably have been waiting
for years to hear that.
I meant it.
I know.
Of course,
it is also the surest way
to screw up
what we do have now.
What do we have now?
We're friends.
Maybe we should try that
for a while.
[Sighs]
You falling in that pool
was probably
the funniest thing
I've ever seen
in my entire life.
[Chuckles]
Hey, where's Kevin?
I dumped him.
Oh, that's -- I'm sor--
Are you okay?
Yeah.
You know,
sometimes I think maybe --
Haley's gay?
Yep.
Yeah.
[Both chuckle]
Oh, these girls,
they're just...amazing.
Hey, what's happening
with the old Mutiny building?
I mean,
I can't believe
they spent all this money
redecorating
and didn't even change
the stupid lock.
Donna: Whoa, carpet.
Yeah.
And look at
all this glass.
Yeah, this was Comet.
Uh, okay, so Gordon
was in your office.
Oh, of course.
And Joe was in mine.
Um, oh.
Gordon rewired the ethernet
so it patched down
through the ceiling,
which was really genius.
[Laughs]
What?
You remember
when, uh, Lev and Yo-Yo
took the fish tank
full of sea monkeys
and they moved it
over by the fridge?
Oh, yeah,
and Carl reached over it
trying to get
to the Better Cheddars
and he spilled it
all over himself.
Yeah,
and he ruined his pants.
He ruined his pants.
So he had to strip them off,
and he was wearing --
what was that?
He was wearing that thing.
It was like a jock strap.
No, no, no,
it was bikini briefs.
Oh, my God.
It was like a French cut.
[Both laugh]
[Both sigh]
Didn't he sit, like,
right here?
No, Carl, he was
over here by Wonderboy.
Cameron: Oh.
Hey, whatever happened
to Annabelle?
The mannequin?
Yeah.
Um, [chuckles]
Well...
Bodie took mushrooms
and immolated her
on the roof
during a lunar eclipse.
[Laughs]
Those guys.
You know Bodie
has four kids now, right?
Get out.
Yes.
And, uh, oh,
Wonderboy teaches at NYU,
but he teaches, like,
video art.
Oh, cool.
What about Carl?
Porn.
Oh, of course,
'cause the mustache.
No, he --
he hosts it on a website
and he charges.
[Laughs]
He has a huge house out
in Arcadia or somewhere.
Yeah.
What would it be?
If we were to do it
all over again?
I'm out of ideas.
Okay, then,
how would we run it?
Well...
we'd call it, um --
I don't know.
Phoenix.
Oh, I like it.
[Chuckles]
Equal equity.
Co-founders.
Equal say in everything.
Mm-hmm.
And we'd just grow
at our own pace this time.
Like, really enjoy the ride.
What if we did
24 months of pure R&amp;D?
Just focus on ideas
way outside the box.
Yeah.
You remember our first week
at Phoenix?
Just you, me,
and that one guy we hired
out of Cal Poly.
I remember our Series A.
And then we went public.
Right.
We had to start making
some hard decisions,
maybe a partnership
with a bigger company,
and we had to sacrifice
some of the culture.
Yeah,
but it worked for a while.
But eventually
we had to let some people go,
streamline some things.
And still
we kept losing ground.
We started arguing about
the direction of the company.
I strategized a safe play
to keep things afloat.
And I dug my heels in.
We fought about it.
But it didn't destroy us
this time.
No.
But still,
we were at an impasse.
And then soon enough,
the decision got made
for us.
[Sighs]
And we walked away
friends.
♪♪
Hey.
It was a pleasure working
with you at Phoenix.
♪♪
I loved every minute of it.
[Sighs]
♪♪
[Drawer closes]
[Tape player clicks]
Gordon:
8, 7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1.
Now, how we doing?
Close your eyes.
Does anything feel weird?
'Cause that's what this is.
Feeling weird is --
is how you know
you're still here.
♪♪
All right, now,
when was the last time you ate?
Because all a human needs
is food, water, and rest.
You got to remind yourself
that you're just
160 pounds of goo
in the middle
of a very big universe.
So whatever's
burning you up right now,
just know that it'll fade.
Every problem feels big
in the moment,
but, Gordon, you know better.
So...focus on just being
being.
And then try to look up
from your computer
every once in a while.
♪♪
I want to try and see you
as much as I can,
but I should be
through Tallahassee
in the next couple weeks, so...
you know, I thought
I could, uh, come by.
Yeah.
Okay, well,
then I'll see you then.
Yeah, I will, Mom.
Okay.
[Sighs]
[Indistinct conversations]
Donna: Did you get her?
Yeah.
Good.
So, it's a busy week
for you?
Oh, yeah, sort of.
We got a 3-D imaging company
presenting at COMDEX,
so, you know,
it's just COMDEX.
Yeah.
Oh, COMDEX.
[Both chuckle]
Okay, well, let's do it.
What you tried to do
24 hours ago.
I'm glad I got waylaid.
Yeah, me, too.
Hey, I'll get breakfast.
Oh, no, no.
Give me that.
No, no, no.
Let's split it.
You're unemployed.
Save your money.
Fair enough.
Meet you outside.
Thank you.
[Sighs]
[Door bells ring]
[Keys clack]
[Cash register opens]
♪♪
Donna: Cameron.
What is it?
♪♪
I have an idea.
[Peter Gabriel's
"Solsbury Hill" plays]
[Engine revs]
♪ Climbing up on Solsbury Hill ♪
♪ I could see the city light ♪
♪ Wind was blowing,
time stood still ♪
[Engine shuts off]
♪ Eagle flew out of the night ♪
♪ He was something to observe ♪
♪ Came in close,
I heard a voice ♪
♪ Standing stretching
every nerve ♪
♪ Had to listen,
had no choice ♪
♪ I did not believe
the information ♪
♪ Just had to trust
imagination ♪
♪ My heart going
boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ "Son," he said ♪
♪ "Grab your things
I've come to take you home" ♪
♪♪
♪ Yeah, back home ♪
♪ To keep in silence
I resigned ♪
♪ My friends would think
I was a nut ♪
♪ Turning water into wine ♪
♪ Open doors
would soon be shut ♪
♪ So I went from day to day ♪
♪ Thought my life was in a rut ♪
♪ Till I thought of
what I'd say ♪
♪ Which connection
I should cut ♪
♪ I was feeling part of
the scenery ♪
♪ I walked right out of
the machinery ♪
[School bell rings]
♪ My heart going
boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ "Hey" he said ♪
♪ "Grab your things
I've come to take you home" ♪
♪♪
♪ Yeah, back home ♪
♪ When illusion spin her net ♪
♪ I'm never where I want to be ♪
♪ And liberty, she pirouette ♪
♪ When I think that I am free ♪
♪ Watched by empty silhouettes ♪
♪ Who close their eyes
but still can see ♪
♪ No one taught them etiquette ♪
♪ I will show another me ♪
♪ Today I don't need
a replacement ♪
♪ I'll tell them what the smile
on my face meant ♪
♪ My heart going
boom, boom, boom ♪
Let me start
by asking a question.
♪ I said ♪
♪ "You can keep my things,
they've come to take me home" ♪
♪♪