MAN [ON PA]:
Good afternoon, Greendale.
I am your dean
with a few corrections
to the fall class catalogue.
Cosmology should be
Cosmetology.
Astrology should be
Astronomy.
The students on the cover
should be smiling,
but that's a matter
of opinion.
Whoever is growing
a small patch of cannabis
behind the gymnasium,
congratulations,
you have won a cruise.
Report to security
to claim your tickets.
In order to increase awareness
of homelessness,
security has been given
binoculars.
In campus news,
the debate over our library's
PA system continues,
with some students suggesting
its volume be lowered,
while others question
its very purpose.
More on that story
as it unfolds.
That dude makes a lot
of announcements.
I like it.
It makes every 10 minutes
feel like a new scene
of a TV show.
The illusion lasts until
someone says something
they never say on TV,
like how much life is like TV.
There, it's gone.
Jeff's running late again.
What a shame.
We should get started--
No, I think we should wait
for Jeff before we start.
But when Jeff gets here,
we could talk to him,
as a group,
about his tardiness.
Oh, come on now. Don't use
that word around Abed.
If you want me to have
a chat with Jeff, I'd do it.
We've got a bond going,
kind of, sort of like brothers.
Hope your mom didn't make you
take baths together.
One of you
would have been like 30.
That's funny.
Jeff probably comes late
so he doesn't have to
sit through your tardiness.
Sorry, Abed.
Hey, will you guys have
some self-respect?
You are
obsessing over someone
who does not give you
a second thought.
In Guatemala,
journalists are being killed
by their own government.
What's happening
in Guatemala?
Nothing.
Journalists
are being murdered?
Every day in that country,
people are being killed
for speaking out.
The worst part of it is,
when it's all over...
Spoilers.
...it's as if it never happened.
Hey, Abed.
ABED: Hm?
Real stories,
they don't have spoilers.
You understand that TV
and life are different, right?
Hey.
[ALL CHEERING]
My lady.
My lord.
Hey, baby.
Hi, sweetie.
You smell nice. Vitamin P.
Morning, Jeffrey. People were
jazzed to see me too.
Word them up.
Word them everywhere.
Good entrance. Thank you.
It was for you.
Britta.
Hey, Jeff.
Think there's something
that the group
would like
to talk to you about.
[ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Okay. If you're gonna
study with people,
it would be cool
to show up on time.
Oh. Were you waiting?
ABED: No.
I just got here.
TROY: No.
You guys usually spend
the first 20 minutes
talking about
your interesting lives
and your cool emotional
problems.
I feel like I never have
anything to offer.
BOTH: Ohh.
JEFF: No. Truth is,
my life is emptier
than this three-ring binder.
Annie, do you have any Spanish
notes that might fit in there?
Wow. Double-spaced.
Thank you.
So, what's a guy gotta do
to get a C around here?
[GROUP LAUGHS]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
BRITTA:
Good study.
ABED:
Thanks for good study.
See you later.
Hey, you know what today is?
It's the two-week anniversary
of my horrible first impression.
There's a card for that?
Not specifically.
But if you think of grandsons
as metaphors for friendship,
I think you'll agree with
this Transformer here
that it's time for ours
to become a man
by reading from the Torah.
You're harmless enough
to me.
A life full of ups and downs
has given me douche-ray vision.
But those are good people
in there,
and they trust and respect you,
and watching you exploit them
bums me out.
Exploit them?
They're my friends.
Can I bring your car around?
No, Abed, I don't want you
bring my car around.
I'll bring yours around,
good guy.
You get going, all right?
You're cute but selfish,
and narcissistic to the point
of near-delusion.
She said I was cute.
Tell you what. You take her.
I have less to prove.
Jeff, you can't pursue
people so desperately.
It starts to
creep them out.
Why don't we get a beer?
I'll give you advice,
and we can have what the kids
are calling a sausage fest.
I'm not much of a sausage guy,
Pierce. Maybe next time.
Next time then.
Hey.
Britta, will you tell us more
about Guatemala?
I wanna be political.
That's good. You should discover
that stuff on your own.
We need your help. We've been
living on the wrong side.
You're like Jodie Foster
or Susan Sarandon.
You'd rather keep it real
than be likeable.
Can you at least tell us
what to Google?
You could start with the
journalist Chacata-Panecos.
Wrote an article critical of the
government and they killed him.
That's horrible.
Can we have a protest?
I wanna protest something.
A candlelight vigil,
like lesbians on the news.
I could make brownies.
[BOTH GIGGLE]
Brownies?
Every once in a while,
a student will ask:
"Señor Chang,
why do you teach Spanish?"
[CHUCKLES]
They say it just like that.
"Why do you teach Spanish?"
Why you.
Why not math?
[STUDENT CLEARS THROAT]
Why not photography?
Why not martial arts?
I mean, surely it must be
in my nature to instruct you
in something that's
ancient and secret
like, building a wall that
you can see from outer space.
Well, I'll tell you why
I teach Spanish.
It is none of your business,
okay?
Now, I don't wanna have
any conversations about what a
[IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
mysterious,
inscrutable man I am.
[LAUGHING
IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I am a Spanish genius!
In español my nickname
is El Tigre Chino.
[SQUAWKING AND GRUNTING]
Because my knowledge
will bite her face off.
So don't question Señor Chang
or you'll get bit.
Yeah, bit. Yeah, bit.
Okay, Friday mañana,
we'll be having conversations
with the rest of the class,
using some phrases we learned.
You'll be partnering up
in pairs of dos.
Heh.
So if you look
under your desk,
you will find a card with either
a picture or a word on it, okay?
Por ejemplo, Blondie, aqui,
has a card with a picture
of a house on it.
So that means the person
with the card
with the word "casa" on it
is her partner.
Comprende, Star-Burns?
Okay, see you Friday, find your
partners, have a great day.
And what do we say
at the end of every class?
[ALL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Come on, hands.
Ninety percent of Spanish.
[ALL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
CHANG: Good.
Abed, Abed, Abed.
Do you want to trade cards?
No.
I'll give you 20 bucks.
Fifty bucks.
No.
Don't want money.
Want your shirt.
What?
I've had my eye on it
since registration.
Fine. Give me your card.
I don't think you understand.
I wanna wear it out of here.
Thanks. Gracias.
Gracias.
What are the odds?
Are you sure you didn't
adjust the odds?
I know Abed's been eyeing
that shirt for three weeks.
It's almost like you gave it
to him so he would switch cards.
I gave Abed my shirt
because I'm not selfish.
Which is I guess
you'll discover
while we are working on this.
Tomorrow night?
Dinner, drinks?
That's something we should
discuss with our partners.
Oh, see, I did switch cards.
[♪♪♪]
Can you believe this?
What are the odds?
That's a nice shirt.
Wanna sell it?
Yes.
PIERCE:
What's the moist towelette
industry like?
Oh, believe me,
it's nothing like the product.
No, it's a hard,
dry, large business.
Destroyed all my marriages.
It didn't help any that
I can't have children.
I'm not sterile.
In fact it's a rare condition
called hyper-virility.
My sperm shoot through the egg
like bullets. Heh.
Can you believe that?
I can't.
But you can,
so that's fine.
So the assignment is to write
a Spanish conversation
using those five phrases--
Ooh.
Hemingway's lemonade.
Don't need to make this
a long evening.
What am I,
a piece of garbage to you?
What? No.
[CHUCKLES]
Got you. Hey, come on,
let's have one drink
before we work.
Mm, mm, mm.
To the empowerage of words.
To the irony
of that sentence.
So, what's up with you?
It seems like you got a burr
up your ass or something.
Well, I guess that it's, uh...
I think it's Britta.
Forget Britta. All you have
to know about her is her name.
What is she, a water filter?
I mean, heh-heh, she's ugly.
Okay.
Why don't we start
with me saying, donde--
What the hell are you doing?
Our assignment.
Oh, no, no, no.
This is the first time
people are gonna see
Winger and Hawthorne together.
We're gonna show them
we're to be reckoned with.
Come on, let's brainstorm
some story ideas.
Better yet, before we do that,
let's ask ourselves...
...what is a story?
Oh, my God in heaven.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Guatemala, we hate
If you like that brownie,
you're gonna hate
what's going on in Guatemala.
Google it.
Oh, hey, hey.
Hi.
Raise the truth.
Okay, once it gets dark,
I hand out the candles,
and we do what's called
a speechless protest.
We put tape over our mouths
and gather hand in hand
in a sea
of outraged silence.
[RAP MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Star-Burns, no, no.
[MUSIC STOPS]
What's gotten into you?
This is not how you do this.
We know it's not how you do it.
Because we're doing everything.
But this is tacky and lame.
I didn't mean that.
I didn't mean that. I'm sorry.
What I meant to say
was that this cause
is really personal to me.
Are you saying that
we're not allowed to protest?
Britta,
you sound like Guatemala.
Somebody has a case of
"likes to use fringe politics
to make themselves feel special
but doesn't ever do anything."
Itis.
No, I do things. I--
I went to--
I don't do anything.
[♪♪♪]
What can I do?
You can hang
the Chacata-Panecos piñata.
You guys realize
he was beaten to death?
That's where we
got the idea from.
Poignant.
PIERCE:
All right.
[SIGHS]
Okay, tell me
what I've got so far.
What we have so far?
Well, we have something
incredibly long
and very confusing,
and a little homophobic.
And really, really,
specifically, surprisingly
and gratuitously critical
of Israel.
It's called "Two Conquistadors."
Should probably be dos.
I mean, it is Spanish class.
Oh, which reminds me.
The only thing not included
in this epic
are the five phrases required
to get me a passing grade.
You're right.
Needs more work.
What are you guys doing?
I have no idea.
Headed to the demonstration.
What, hippies?
Some cause Britta's into.
ABED: It's a silent protest,
lots of candles. Gets the ladies
in the mood for social change.
Good chance to put miles
on this shirt.
You realize these conversations
are due in the morning?
Oh, yeah. Right.
What do you wanna do?
[BOTH SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Pfft. Hacks.
Okay, what do we do
about the ending of act two?
I'll tell you
what we're going to do.
We are gonna take this
and we're gonna put it
in a museum for crazy people.
Then we're gonna take this
and memorize five phrases
tomorrow morning before class.
Good night.
Wait a minute. You're bailing
on our first sausage fest?
This is your definition
of friendship?
No, this is my definition
of you trying way too hard
and me finding it harder
and harder to stay polite.
This was a fine way to spend
an evening devoid of hope,
but the woman I kind of like
is out in the moonlight
caring about something
stupid.
This is my chance to show her
that I care enough to act
like I care about it too.
That's all you had to say.
That was it? Oh.
Would've been great if I had
done that two hours ago.
[♪♪♪]
Nice sign.
Thanks.
I like what you've done
with the place.
I think was a little too harsh
on you. I'm not perfect.
I am. I'd be happy
to show you the ropes.
PIERCE:
Awesome.
Look at awesome
Jeffrey Winger.
Too awesome for old Pierce
with your hip shirts
and your gelled hair
and your cool tape
over your mouth.
Why is everybody wearing
tape over their mouth?
It's a protest, Pierce.
Oh, good.
Because I know what I'd like to
protest. How much you hurt me.
Conflicts like these
will bring us together
as an unlikely family.
You have horrible breath.
You constantly blow me off, then
you want me to do your homework.
Then you tell me
I'm trying too hard
to be your friend
so you have to go.
You had to come out here
to pretend to care
about the stupid stuff
she cares about.
His words, not mine.
He is paraphrasing.
I got an idea. Why don't you
go get a cup of coffee
and hold some waitress hostage
with a monologue about sperm.
I'll show you
some sperm, buddy.
Is this your idea?
What the hell? I'm on fire!
No, I'm not ready to die.
[PIERCE SCREAMING]
Oh, he's-- He's--
[WATER SPLASHES]
He's jumped in the fountain.
He's fine.
WOMAN: Please call 911.
Have you seen it?
We did it, girl. Page three.
It's about Pierce,
but listen to that paragraph.
"The incident occurred
during a protest"
"regarding events
in Guatemala." Awareness!
This is a real damn newspaper.
There's a Marmaduke in here.
It's more than
I ever accomplished.
Did you know about the
ethnic cleansing in Burma?
We need to bust out
that brownie mix.
[BOTH SQUEAL THEN GIGGLE]
Morning.
Oh, no, I get it.
Garfield's wishing me a Arbor
Day, you'd like a fresh start.
Nice try.
It's actually Secretaries Day.
It says I'm sorry about
crashing your protest
with that drunken,
self-immolating baby boomer.
We don't blame you. Pierce has
always been on my watch list.
That dude is crazy. He told me
girls have two pee holes.
I sang carols at a nursing home.
I've seen the face of dementia,
and last night, I saw it again.
You know what he did
that's really crazy?
He offered me a $100
to switch cards with him
just so he could be
partners with Jeff.
I think he thought getting
closer to Jeff
would bring him respect
in the group.
I think he spent his whole life
looking out for himself,
and he would trade it all
for a shot at some family.
[PIERCE &amp; CHANG
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
CHANG: Hola, class.
ALL: Hola.
CHANG:
Time for our presentations.
First up was supposed
to be Jeff and Pierce,
but Pierce explained
the situation to me.
There was a falling out, things
were said, people were betrayed.
[WHISPERING]
Wow.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Jeff, having heard
Pierce's side of the story,
the only humane thing to do
would be to give you a C
and let Pierce do
his presentation alone.
If that sounds fair to you.
That doesn't sound fair
to me at all.
I understand if you don't
wanna be my friend.
But this thing that
we've created,
it is bigger than
the both of us,
and it deserves
to be done right.
[♪♪♪]
All right.
Okay, um, guys, why are
there costumes involved?
These are short conversations.
They're not supposed to take--
Your breath away?
Well, tough.
You ready, amigo?
Si.
[AIMEE MANN'S
"WISE UP" PLAYING]
♪ It's not ♪
♪ What you thought ♪
♪ When you first ♪
Began it ♪
♪ You got ♪
♪ What you want ♪
♪ Now you can hardly ♪
♪ Stand it though
By now you know ♪
♪ It's not ♪
♪ Going to stop ♪
♪ Till you wise up ♪
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
F, F-minus.
What?
What? Did you say S?
So...
that was one of the worst
things I have ever seen.
Which I guess makes being a part
of it a pretty selfless act.
So I'm impressed.
How do you know
I didn't do it
just to get another shot
at you?
A smart guy like you would know
that no woman in that class
will be able to look at you
as a sexually viable candidate
ever again.
[MATT &amp; KIM'S "DAYLIGHT"
PLAYING]
No, I know.
I thought of that.
She looked back.
Aah!
You did an all right job
up there, my friend.
Thanks, Pierce.
PIERCE:
You got this thing you do
with your face
when you're trying to be
funny, forces people
to think about how cool
you think you are.
[PIERCE CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY]
[BEATBOXING]
[RAPPING IN SPANISH]
Yeah, boy, boy.
Yeah.
What? It's 2009.
Word.