[♪♪♪]
Hey, man.
My name is Jeff.
I'm trying to lock down
my schedule
before the deadline.
I heard this class
was a cakewalk.
Are you passing it?
Do you like Dane Cook?
Yeah, he's awesome.
[WHISPERS]
So far so good.
Death, so called,
Is a thing
That makes men weep,
And yet a third of life
Is spent in sleep.
Open your text books
to page 37.
Now, close them
and throw them away.
Throw it away.
Ha-ha-ha!
For those who are new,
the motto of this class,
carpe diem, seize the day,
no tests, no papers.
You want an A?
Live in the moment.
Jackpot.
Take off your shoes.
Take your shoes off,
throw them away.
Throw them over there.
Today we learn to walk.
Get up and walk out the door.
This day could be your last.
You could die in your sleep.
You could get hit by a bus.
That mole is raised
and dark,
it's not a good combo.
You are new.
Yes, I'm new.
But I'll be old too soon.
Carpe diem, sir,
carpe diem.
Ha-ha-ha! I like it!
Voice command.
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]
[BEEPS]
Voice command.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Voice comm--
[BEEPS]
Would you please use
the buttons?
Okay, grandpa.
[IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
Achoo!
Oh. God bless you, dear.
[BOTH GIGGLE]
What's so funny?
You guys, I found it.
The ultimate blow-off class.
Professor Whitman,
he thinks
he's in Dead Poets Society.
There's no tests,
there's no work,
it's just day seizing.
The deadline to enroll
is tomorrow.
I suggest you all do it.
Well, some of us are here
to actually learn things.
I'm in.
Me too, it sounds educational.
I love Robin Williams.
Abed?
Not a fan. In every movie,
there's an authority figure
that gets mad at him
for making people laugh.
No, are you going
to take the class?
Oh, can't. My dad will
only pay for classes
that will help me run
the family restaurant.
It's been struggling
since 2001.
9/11 was pretty much the 9/11
of the falafel business.
So your dad has your whole
life planned out for you?
Are you even
interested in falafel?
I'm interested
in making movies.
But my Dad says all media's
Western propaganda
that negatively
stereotypes Arabs.
He should see Aladdin,
Jafar was a badass.
SHIRLEY: Yes, he was.
TROY: He was.
Abed, how much
does a film class cost?
Seventy dollars.
Britta?
Jeff?
Britta.
Isn't Abed's dad
a hardcore Muslim?
They're not as understanding
as Christians.
You could get your head cut off
with a salami sword.
Shirley, that's
the most racist thing
I've ever heard.
Is that racist?
Pierce will beat
that in one minute.
ABED:
This is really nice of you.
The memo says,
"For dreams."
BOTH:
Aw.
You guys, are we going
to study Spanish,
or keep getting involved
in each other's personal lives?
[IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
Achoo!
Hey, Troy sneezes
like a girl.
How about I pound you
like a boy?
That didn't come out right.
Why don't you leave him alone
with his cute baby sneezes.
You're not my mother.
She's not?
[CLOCK BEEPS]
Twenty-nine seconds.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
[♪♪♪]
What's your name?
Shirley Bennett.
Shirley, you get an A...
Oh.
...if you can tell me
why you are here at Greendale.
What did I tell you?
Okay, but, uh, never again.
WHITMAN: Shirley?
To get a degree in business
so I can sell my baked goods
and whatnot on the Internet.
Why are you here?
To get a degree in business
so I can sell my baked goods
and whatnot on the Internet.
Why are you here?!
Because I wasted 15 years
of my life
on a man who left me
with nothing but stretch marks
and a foggy memory
of two bland orgasms.
And now it's time to get
what's mine.
Day seized.
[ALL CLAPPING]
WHITMAN:
Only when we stop stopping
our lives
can we begin
to start starting them.
Ms. Edison here,
for example,
would rather write about
what happens to other people
than live
what is happening to her.
I thought
there might be a quiz.
Well, here's
a quiz for you.
Why did the pretty
young girl die alone,
surrounded
by sweater-wearing cats
who were trained
to use human toilets?
Get up on your desk.
Come on, stand on your desk.
Up on your desk.
She made it. Ha-ha!
Everyone,
stand on your desks.
Up, up, up. Come on.
Rise, rise,
rise above the programming.
All your lives you were told,
"don't stand on your desk."
Well, why not?
[ALL GASP]
Oh, what happened? My--
She's okay, go to the nurse,
seize the day.
You know, I was really moved
by your honesty earlier.
Particularly, the part
about, uh,
your husband not being--
Oh!
WHITMAN:
Your homework. Ah.
I want you to swim in a lake
and tell 10 people
that you love them.
Mr. Winger,
may I have a word, please?
SHIRLEY:
Are you okay?
Oh. Oh, maybe,
I'm not.
Hi, Mr. Winger,
I like to think that every life
that passes through
this class is changed.
But there's always
one cocky opportunist
who's just here to coast
and grab an easy A.
Oh, yeah.
His name is Pierce,
I can talk to him for you.
It's actually you,
Mr. Winger.
You have no intention
of seizing the day.
What? Listen, I--
I have never lived
until I met you.
I-- I love you.
There's one down, nine to go.
Not that I need the grade
or even want it.
WHITMAN:
Glad to hear it,
because if you don't
genuinely seize the day
before the end of the week,
then you will be seizing an F
for the semester.
[♪♪♪]
This is no way
to teach accounting.
JEFF:
I have to plan in advance
how to prove that
I live in the moment.
I'd rather take
an actual class,
but now, it's too late
to drop or add.
It is not fair how hard it is
for you to cheat here.
Ah! Hey, how's it going?
How's your film class, buddy?
It's cool. Our first assignment
is a documentary.
They're like real movies
but with ugly people.
I'm learning a lot.
That is so wonderful.
Some people don't like
getting involved
in others' lives.
I think it's great.
Hey, if you're making
a documentary
about Britta
patting herself on the back,
you're gonna need
a backup battery.
I'm doing a movie about my dad.
That is brilliant.
How did he react to you
signing up for the film class?
That part hasn't happened yet.
Here he comes.
Hey, you want to get involved
in my family's business?
Holy war.
Where do I find Mr. Britta?
I'm Mr. Britta.
That's right,
I'm a woman with rights.
And you can see my whole face.
Oh, I get it, because
I'm Arab I must hate women.
Let me tell you something.
I love women.
But I'm getting a major B-word
vibe from you.
Wow, I can't believe I missed
out on getting involved in this.
You go host American Idol, and
you stop messing with my son.
He is a special boy.
I raise him. You don't.
Raising him means
letting him follow dreams.
Dreams are for sleeping.
You don't know that.
It's clinically proven.
So is polio.
You lost me.
Abed wants to study film.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
What's he saying?
He says we're leaving.
Tell him you wanna stay
and study film.
I don't think
I'm really in the scene.
See? It's hard to talk
to him before.
Now we have this between us.
Let's go!
Hey. Hey.
Don't touch me.
You-- You don't touch me.
Shut up. Stop.
Sir, you have a right
to your faith
and your family's privacy
but Abed is an adult
and a U.S. citizen.
Right?
Yeah.
And he has the right to stay.
Fine.
You want to raise him?
You raise him, I'm out.
Wait, what?
I had a father like you.
And the day
I finally cut myself loose
is the day
I finally started being happy.
That went well.
I have to make some adjustments
to my film.
Jeff, I think you should play
the role of my father.
I don't want to be your father.
It's perfect.
You already know your lines.
[♪♪♪]
Why are you dressed
like an '80s rapist?
Professor Whitman
comes by here every morning
and I need him to see me
celebrating life.
What's all that?
I am calculating Abed's
expenses for this semester.
There's books, there's meals,
he's renting that camera.
He needs
a little spending money.
Um, all money
is spending money.
Oh, Britta, it's amazing
what you're doing for Abed.
I mean, a lot of people
talk a good game.
But you, you follow through.
I love you.
Shirley, thank you.
Bet that doesn't happen
to you a lot.
It happened yesterday. Shirley's
just doing her homework.
Hillary, thank you
for getting people coffee.
I love you.
Abed, how's it
going, buddy?
Good, my film
is coming together.
Cool tie, Jeff.
Are you wearing that
because you're playing
the role of my dad,
or is it really Christmas?
Definitely Christmas.
Is that a new camera?
ABED: Yeah, it's more expensive
but it lets me adjust
really specific settings
that most people don't notice
or think about.
Hi, I would like a latte,
and Jeff,
let me get you something.
I'm okay.
Oh, come on, I got you.
No, really,
I don't need anything--
You're insulting me.
Look at all this cash.
Okay. I will get a small,
black coffee.
Boo. An ordinary coffee
for an ordinary life.
Good morning,
Professor Whitman.
Sorry, Mr. Winger,
these won't cut it.
Shazbat.
WHITMAN: I shall have--
A birthday cake.
[SNEEZES
IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
[CROWD LAUGHING]
I've seen men
in your situation, Troy.
No, those are
both for me.
You were on top
of the world before
and now, no one
gives a rat's ass.
I can help you
with your image.
First, I'd lose the jacket,
you look like
a high school bitch.
But more importantly,
it's your sneeze.
When I was a CEO,
I had an array
of masculine sneezes
that asserted dominance.
You know, like the explosive
shock-the-room-
into-silence sneeze.
[SNEEZES THEN YELLS]
[SNIFFS]
Or, they draw them in sneeze,
you know.
[PANTING]
You know,
maybe I wouldn't sneeze,
because I'm in control.
You can even use a sneeze
to drive home a point.
Like, I think the Cubs
are gonna win it all this year.
[SNEEZES THEN SNIFFS]
What do you think?
Tell me more.
[♪♪♪]
It's show time.
JEFF:
Hey, everybody, good morning.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, Greendale.
Hi, good morning.
Watch the kite. Uh-oh.
Mind if I get a chance? Oh!
[CHILDREN &amp; JEFF CHATTERING]
Thanks, you guys,
bring it in here. Nice.
Thank you so much, you guys,
that was really fun.
Sloppy and considering the age
of these girls,
unwittingly creepy.
Damn it.
Beat it. Professor.
Will you look
at the amount of work
that I'm putting into this?
I mean, throw me a bone.
Had I not already cried
at the sunrise this morning,
I would be weeping
right now.
What does that mean?
What do you mean, Jeff?
What does your life mean?
How long does it take you
in the morning
to make it look like
you have bed-head?
How many sweatpants-
sports jacket combos
did you try before you found
the one that said,
"I don't care?"
Seize the day, Jeff.
For real.
Go running naked
in a hail storm.
Kiss a girl
in the middle of the day.
Fly a kite,
but do it for yourself.
Or you won't just fail
my class,
you'll fail life.
[♪♪♪]
Thank you.
That guy's really
got your number.
Drop the flower.
I need to talk to you
about Abed.
I went by his film class today,
he wasn't there, he's cutting.
I wanna know why
he would do something like that.
Ask him.
Every time I try
to ask him about it,
he just keeps filming me
and telling me that I'm playing
the role of his mother.
Abed is not normal.
That's what you bought
when you intentionally
tangled yourself in his life.
Look, will you just--
Will you please talk to him?
I've got problems of my own.
I'm out here trying
to seize a day.
[♪♪♪]
What in the hell?
Is he gonna kill us?
Thanks for the pizza, Abed,
I was starving.
Yeah, it's nice,
like a picnic.
Or a family dinner.
It's a study group
and a pizza,
let's not get
carried away.
[BRITTA CLEARS THROAT]
So, Abed.
How's film class?
Good.
Yeah. Did you
go to class today?
Not really.
Well, Britta's paying
for those classes,
don't you think
maybe you should go?
I was shooting my movie.
Your movie is for class.
My movie's more important.
La-la-la.
Someone order seven lattes?
I got that.
No, you don't got it.
I got it, Abed.
I got everything.
What is wrong with you?
All I want to do
is take care of you.
I know you're not stupid,
are you doing this on purpose?
Why won't you answer me?
This is the scene
where you leave.
You better believe it.
Britta.
What do you think, Dad?
I think you are really weird,
Abed.
And I think
the wrong person just left.
[♪♪♪]
Perfect. That's a wrap.
That guy was your dad?
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey.
You don't really have tickets
for Ravi Shankar, do you?
I lied to get you here
because it's time
to communicate.
Communicate?
Have you met Abed?
It's not the two of you
that need to talk.
Hey, wait a minute.
Where's Weezer?
They're coming.
Now, the only reason
why this whole mess got started
is because both of you
wanted the best for Abed.
And I think the lesson
we can all take away from this
is that everyone
should always do
whatever they want,
and leave each other
out of it.
Is that your take?
Let me give you mine.
You and your
pillow-lipped girlfriend
got all up in my stuff
because you wanted
to be cowboys,
and then you turned chicken
when you found out
it would take more than speeches
and guided missiles.
Interesting. I hadn't seen
the Iraq metaphor.
What metaphor? I'm talking
about your speeches
and her guided--
Got it.
The point is, is that Britta
is sorry, right?
Wrong.
Crap.
Abed may not be
a great filmmaker
but that doesn't mean
that he wants to make falafel.
You need to let him
make his own decisions.
Make his own decisions?
Have you met Abed?
You know who he is?
You have no--
JEFF: Guys.
I'm finished.
Britta, Jeff, Dad.
Dad.
[MUSIC PLAYS
OVER COMPUTER]
[CHILDREN GIGGLING]
How's it going, buddy?
I don't want to be your father.
[BABY CRIES]
I think you are weird, Abed.
BRITTA:
Hey, look. I need to talk
to you about Abed.
JEFF:
He's not normal.
[BABY CRYING]
BRITTA:
What is wrong with you?
All I want to do
is take care of you.
Why will you not answer me?
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[BEEPING]
[EKG FLATLINING]
ABED:
What do you think, Dad?
JEFF:
I think you are weird, Abed.
And I think
the wrong person just left.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS
OVER COMPUTER]
It's not exactly Citizen Kane.
[ABED'S DAD SOBS]
[♪♪♪]
[IN ARABIC]
[WHISPERS]
I feel a little out
of the loop here.
[WHISPERS]
That feeling is called
the joy of freedom.
My son is hard to understand.
If making movies help him
be understood,
then I pay for the class.
[MOUTHS WORDS]
[MOUTHING]
I made all this happen.
With falafel as a fallback.
Abed.
Yeah?
Did you do all of that to me
on purpose?
That's not a very nice way
to treat your friends.
Well, Britta,
it isn't called
friend business,
it's called show business.
He's smoking.
Honey, let him leave the nest.
[♪♪♪]
Get your hand off
of my knee.
[SNEEZES LOUDLY]
God-- God bless you.
God bless you.
Thank you.
BRITTA:
For someone who doesn't like
getting involved,
well, I owe you.
You owe me?
That can not be
comfortable for you.
Hey, um--
You should kiss me right now.
[♪♪♪]
Day seized!
We're even.
[WHITMAN LAUGHS]
A plus, Winger.
I know a life-changing kiss
when I see one. Wowee!
[LAUGHING]
Yeah.
Fooled you.
[♪♪♪]
Am I krumping?
No.
Am I krumping now?
This is krumping.
[HIP-HOP MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO]
We-- We're krumping.
No, you're not.
Hit it!
♪ Bang, bang, bang
Bang, bang, bang ♪