A small, fading remnant
of a star.
A white dwarf.
That's right.
I used a memory technique.
Dwarves hate
being called midgets,
and midgets are small.
And what does a star turn
into after it collapses?
A movie of the week.
A black hole.
Right.
Troy,
you could be an astronomer.
There's only one black hole
worth studying.
It's called Sagittarius A.
It's located in the center
of our galaxy,
and it has the density
of 40 suns.
Just like my wiener.
TROY: Ha, ha.
You said "wiener." That's funny.
Pierce and Troy are bonding
through mutual adolescence.
Shut up, fart head.
Poo-poo head.
Hi, everybody. Ha, ha.
Well, look at this group.
Having some kind of meeting
and being so diverse.
There is just-- Boy--
There is just one of
every kind of you, isn't there?
We are missing a pipsqueak,
but we don't want one, beat it.
Uh, Pierce, that's the dean.
You kidding?
Sorry. Just my luck.
Don't let me interrupt.
Sometimes,
I just roll around campus
like a little football.
I can't believe this.
Here I am in a random
conversation about football,
and I'm talking to Troy Barnes,
star quarterback
from Riverside High. Whoa. Heh.
Troy, did you know Greendale
has a football team?
Did you know
they had a football?
Ah. Heh. Good.
That's very funny.
Troy, I was so sorry to hear
about your injury,
but now
that you have recovered,
we would love for you to play
for the Human Beings.
The team's name
is the Human Beings?
My idea. It was the Greendale
Grizzlies, but I thought--
[WHISPERING]
A lot of these students
have been called animals.
Unfortunately, I don't know
what to do about the mascot.
Oh. I could help with that.
I have a wealth of experience
in image management,
icon development,
and Y2K preparedness.
Ooh. Well,
aren't you found money.
Troy, all of your friends
are lining up
to turn Greendale around.
How about you?
ANNIE:
Troy isn't interested
in football.
Getting injured was the best
thing that ever happened.
Whoa. Yoko Ono much?
[DEAN LAUGHING]
Bros before ho's, Troy.
Heh. Listen, man, no offense,
but I was the best
and I finished on top.
I wouldn't play
with a 10-foot pole.
Dean, I'm sure Troy
will sign up for football,
if and when
some accident damages
the part of his brain
that feels pride.
Until then, excuse us.
If you change your mind,
the field is always open.
Figuratively speaking.
Wednesdays and Sundays
it's used as parking overflow
for the megachurch. Okay.
Now let's meet
the minimum requirements
for a language credit.
Yes, but I need to go
to the bathroom first.
Uh, Britta?
Oh, no, I don't have to go.
I'll go with you.
[♪♪♪]
What? She's offended?
Girls go in groups.
Did you learn nothing
from standup comedy in the '90s?
I'm familiar with the concept.
If it's important to Shirley,
I'll go next time.
I'm willing to try some more
mainstream feminine stuff.
Then you should know
nothing says,
"I'm a woman"
like doing it with me.
Nothing says,
"I'm a pig," like you.
Will they or won't they?
Sexual tension.
It makes the group
uncomfortable when you talk
like we're characters in a show.
That's sort of my gimmick.
But we did lean
on that pretty hard last week.
I can lay low for an episode.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ I can't count
The reasons I should stay ♪
JEFF:
Sure you made the right call
on the team?
It looks like
they won something once.
"Most Valued Customer,
Henderson Trophy Cases."
So we should still study
a little more astronomy later.
Maybe over some Milky Ways
or some Mars bars.
Or pancakes.
JEFF:
"I'm Jeff and I'm a student
at Greendale"?
Well, that's not good.
WOMAN:
Wood undergoes rapid oxidation
because it reacts
spontaneously to--
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Seriously.
We've talked about this.
Okay, you have got to turn off
your cell ph--
That's mine. My bad.
[WHISPERING]
I'm going to the bathroom.
Would you like to come with me?
Well, yes. Yes, I would.
Oh, that's nice.
Okay, what's it called?
Antoni--? Hold on.
Does anybody have a pen?
A pen?
No one has a pen.
Why would you not bring a pen
to class?
Idiot. No, you're not an idiot.
Ha-ha-ha.
I had my blinker on
about five minutes,
and this "bald but trying
to hide it with a bandana"
loser swooped in.
I couldn't believe it.
BRITTA:
Maybe he didn't see you.
Maybe he had his blinker
on too.
He saw me.
Maybe.
So you got any family, Britta?
BRITTA:
Yeah. Whatever.
My mom
might visit this weekend.
She and I are gonna
get makeovers--
Makeovers. They sure
have us programmed right.
[IN ROBOT VOICE]
I am a female pleasure unit.
I require a new coat of paint.
Something
I thought might be fun.
Here's something I think
might be fun.
Let's find the number of
makeup companies owned by women.
I'll save you the trouble.
It's zero.
Of course, you're saying,
"Aren't you a hypocrite?
You're plastered with glitter
and goo from head to toe
like the rest of us."
I also pay income tax
and pull over for cops.
That doesn't mean
I support a country...
[WHIRRING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Thanks for offering
to design the new mascot.
I have been a little stumped.
Heh. That's no problem.
I took the liberty
of thumbnailing a prototype,
uh, which I modeled
after Da Vinci's Vitruvian Man.
You're offering it, but--
The penis is a little small.
Oh, okay.
It looks a lot like you.
Um, here's the thing.
If we are the Human Beings,
you know,
and we have a mascot
that's just a white guy,
what message are we sending?
Our symbol needs
the diversity of our school
and our species.
So black?
No, because we're not
the Greendale Blacks
or the Greendale Asians,
we are
the Greendale Human Beings.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Yeah.
Sorry to disturb you guys.
Who are looking
at a naked drawing
of Pierce doing jumping jacks.
A quick download?
Uh-- Absolutely.
Excuse me.
Okay. Fill me in later.
[GASPS]
Whoa-oh.
Ah. Good, a pencil.
First of all, I'm flattered.
Oh, well,
you're a very photogenic man.
Is that real bed head,
or do you put something
in there? Can I?
It's crispy.
I was thinking about
the four disembodied heads
and I thought,
"Where's the heart?
The soul?
Where's the different
poster design?"
Those were
less than personable.
Which is why I went
with the full bodies
in these mailers
we have going out.
Ta-ta-ta.
Mailers? I didn't give
permission for this.
Did you not read
the release agreement
on the back
of your registration?
I'm starting to see why
someone used to be a lawyer.
Look, if someone
from the outside were to find--
Okay, if someone
from the outside
were to find out I am a student
at a community college,
that could have
a negative impact
on my future career.
Oh.
Goodness. Look what
we have stumbled onto.
An opportunity to help
each other out.
I suppose I wouldn't need
this promotional campaign
if I could announce
to the press
that Troy Barnes
is playing football here.
He's been pretty clear
about declining that offer.
If you said jump,
he'd say, "How high?"
If you said stop,
he'd say "Hammer time."
You get what I mean? Hmm?
No, I need another example.
You know,
I didn't realize before,
but we should send those out
to local businesses.
Law firms, lawyer companies,
legal gatherings.
You trying to blackmail me?
I think so.
Gentlemen, I present to you
the Greendale Human Being.
That's a falcon with a gun.
[♪♪♪]
It's a falcon
with an erection.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, hi, Abed.
Hmm.
Bye. He's just laying low.
Are you going
to the bathroom?
Uh-- Yes.
I'll go with you.
You know what? I'm good.
She probably just, you know,
had to go number two.
Okay, what's
the closest planet to Earth?
Planet Hollywood?
Ha-ha-ha.
That's not the right answer,
but it shows
how fun astronomy can be.
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Oh, we're studying,
so Troy's busy.
The galaxy's
not going anywhere.
I'll bring him back.
JEFF:
Ever miss being a quarterback?
I miss being the best
at something.
I miss having a coach.
TROY:
I miss knowing what to think.
You still know what to think.
Oh, good.
After the dean talked
to you about football,
you and I were thinking
the same thing.
That dude looks like Moby.
We were thinking,
what if Troy did play?
You'd be surprised
at how many of
your favorite players
got started
at community college.
Really? Name one.
Who's your favorite player?
Me. Whoa.
Maybe you
and I should go
check out
the Greendale Thunderdome.
[IMITATES CROWD CHEERING]
[GRUNTING]
The dome arrives later.
It comes with thunder.
Let me tell you a little secret
about me.
Every day,
on my way to school,
I drive through downtown,
past the courthouse,
just to get a glimpse
of the world I once ruled.
And I just wanna jump out
of my car,
run up the steps and exploit
the legal system for profit.
But I can't. I'm locked out
of my old kingdom.
You're not.
You see what I'm saying?
You're saying
I could be a lawyer.
I'm saying
you're a football player.
It's in your blood.
That's racist.
Your soul.
Your eyes?
That's gay?
Homophobic.
That's black.
That's racist.
Damn.
When you played,
you were a god.
You're not playing
and you're not.
I'd tell you do the math,
but math isn't important.
The only thing
important is this.
But Annie said--
Annie said Benjamin Button
was compelling.
A smart girl, but
sometimes she's just wrong.
Eighty-five, go long.
It's like a drug, isn't it?
Feel it, Troy. Throw it!
The scoreboard lights up.
There will be
a scoreboard there.
It's complete. Nice catch.
The girls, the glory,
the scouts, the career.
It starts
when you join this team.
Is that linebacker
a pregnant woman?
You can meet them later,
but this decision
has to be yours, T-Bone.
And this decision
has to be yes.
How did you know
my nickname was T-Bone?
You're a football player
and your name begins with T.
Your name begins with T.
[♪♪♪]
Britta?
Oh, are you finished?
I have to go, but apparently,
I failed yesterday's tryouts
for the position
of bathroom companion.
I wasn't trying
to hurt your feelings.
You didn't hurt
my feelings, Shirley.
I don't need to go
with other people.
I was just trying
to throw you a bone
because I like you.
Keep that bone.
Listening to a story
about a stranger
pissing me off and taking
the stranger's side?
You can't talk
about your own business
but insinuate my mama's a robot
because we want makeovers.
That is the ladies room.
A place where ladies share,
listen, support each other,
and discretely eliminate waste.
And I like you too.
I even like that
you're a little hard,
but if you can't learn
to be soft in there,
you need to pee alone.
I've peed alone my whole life.
Women have always hated me.
I don't even know
how it started.
Maybe it was when I got boobs
before everybody--
Shh.
Not out here.
In there.
Whoo! Ha, ha.
Troy, Troy, the wonder boy.
You dropped your books,
Poindexter. Heh-heh-heh.
Troy, I've been
waiting for an hour.
It's all right. I'm worth it.
♪ Hip hop, body don't stop ♪
♪ Riverside got the broom
Don't need a mop ♪
♪ Put your team in a box
A ribbon on top ♪
♪ Not John Kerry
We don't flip flop ♪
Troy,
♪ Say, ho ♪
why are you doing
our conservative high school's
outdated fight rap? Have you
been playing football?
Threw the skin around.
I still got it.
Uhn, uhn, uhn. Doosh! Uhn.
But you knew we had
an Astronomy test tomorrow.
Class blows.
What I need to know
about the universe
is I'm at the center
of it.
♪ Oh
Bing, bong, sing along ♪
♪ Your team's Al Gore
Your views are wrong ♪
Troy, stop.
Don't become
this person again.
This isn't
the real you.
This is the jock that totally
ignored the only people
that liked him
for non-superficial reasons
but weren't allowed to say
because
their parents are bigots.
Huh?
Football is bad for you.
Jeff said you'd say that.
Jeff-- What now?
Troy. Troy, Troy, Troy.
That's my name.
I think if we add in a little
bit of Phylicia Rashad,
we'll be in better shape.
Right.
That beige is light.
Um-- Wow.
Yeah, yeah.
We are developing
the perfect mascot.
No stereotypical identifiers
from any race or gender.
This is a chart of the features
we're staying away from.
Pan-Asian eye folds, uh,
Irish chins, women's breasts.
Is that Seal?
That is our human color wheel.
It goes from Seal
to Seal's teeth.
What do you think?
JEFF:
I think
not being racist
is the new racism.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What happened to the prototype?
Ooh, I left the nose
in the kiln.
PELTON:
Oh.
So Troy is gonna play football.
Yes.
Which means
I'll be getting rid of these.
No, uh, I won't mail these out
but they are staying with me
until the press announces
Troy is a part of the team.
I want him
at that pep rally tonight.
Reporters are gonna be there.
We're gonna unveil
the new mascot
and things are finally
going to start turning around.
Oh, and my ex-therapist
is gonna think twice
before he makes fun of my job!
Here it is. Still hot.
Ooh. Ow.
I'm gonna get
some more coffee.
You want anything?
A Desmond Tutu
with enough cream to make
a Lou Diamond Phillips.
La Bamba. Got it.
[♪♪♪]
ANNIE:
Aha!
I've been following you.
How much did the dean
pay you to make Troy play?
I'm not having a conversation
with someone
who emerges from a bush.
Because I'm right?
Because I'm not in
a commercial for cereal.
The dean has pictures
of me.
Horrible pictures of me.
Attending his school.
For that,
you've convinced Troy
to flush his life down
football's toilet again?
Britta's right. You are
the most selfish person.
All that is gonna end now.
I'm telling him what kind
of friend you are.
Tell him you're hopelessly
in love with him.
High school
must have been tough.
Waiting for a superstar
to notice you.
But here, here, he's all alone
and he needs so much help.
Did you enroll
in all his classes
or were you worried
that might freak him out?
The important thing is
you are there for him.
The important thing is you are
the only one there for him.
And you don't really care
what he wants,
as long as you don't have
to share him with the world.
Because, really,
you are just as selfish as I am.
You're just not
as good at it yet.
You're right.
I could never be
as good as you.
Probably,
because I actually care.
Profound,
but technically meaningless.
Don't bother trying that thing
women do where they walk away
and make the guy feel like crap,
because it won't happen.
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
[WHISPERS]:
Damn it.
Shirley, will you please come
to the bathroom with me?
Where's Shirley?
Shirley's not coming.
But, uh,
I'm here to listen, girl.
Why do we inflict so much pain
on ourselves for men?
I don't know, sweetie.
Maybe it's because men
make the world go around?
Kleenex?
[SNIFFLES THEN SOBS]
I've been infatuated with Troy.
Now he's joining football.
Now he'll have his pick
of the litter,
and I'll never
get to be with him.
Oh, Annie, screw him.
There are guys out there
that would kill to be with you.
If Troy isn't one of them,
that's him failing
your standards. You got that?
You're right.
I can't control him.
And if I truly cared about him,
I wouldn't want to.
Thanks for talking to me,
Britta.
It really helped.
Seriously?
Yes.
Who's my girl?
[ALL GIGGLE]
Excuse me.
I did it. I did it.
Oh, yes, you did.
[♪♪♪]
[CHANTING IN DISTANCE]
PLAYERS [CHANTING]:
Human Beings, Human Beings,
Human Beings.
Human Beings, Human Beings.
Troy. Troy.
Don't go in there, man.
What?
You got the most you were going
to get in high school.
A life of disillusionment
and depression
begins on the other side
of that door.
Is this your first
pep rally or something?
You told me football was
the most important thing.
Buckle up, I was exaggerating.
It's kind of my gimmick.
Let me tell you something.
No, let me.
That keg flip
that cost me my scholarship?
Yeah.
I hurt myself on purpose.
What?
There was a scout coming
to the final game,
and I couldn't take
the pressure.
So I took the easy way out.
When you showed me
that field,
I saw there was nothing
to worry about.
I could play football
for fun.
Have you seen these guys?
There is nowhere to go but up.
Dude, we have feelings.
I don't know about you,
but I know I ended up here
because things
weren't that great out there.
[♪♪♪]
Try accepting
where you're at, man.
Take a pottery class
or something.
TROY:
♪ Greendale, we're number one
Nancy Pelosi is no fun ♪
[ANNOUNCER SPEAKS
INDISTINCTLY ON MIC]
[♪♪♪]
Hey.
I've decided to support Troy.
They deploy things in football.
I went for rhyme over clarity.
Look, I'm, uh--
I'm really sorry about before.
I just think we were both wrong.
Really?
Because I'm an 18-year-old girl
and you made me cry in public.
Hmm. Okay, maybe I was
a little more wrong.
I should grow up
and make peace with being here.
It's not like Greendale
is gonna kill me.
Holy crap.
[SCREAMS]
Sorry. Hey, say hello
to our ethnically neutral
mascot, the Human Being.
The costume makes it difficult
for him to see.
[MASCOT GRUNTING]
He can't move his mouth either.
But take it from me,
that's human for "hello."
Let's get you
into the pep rally.
Great idea.
Let's do it.
We've solved racism.
What's next?
PELTON:
Let's do something
for little people. Or albinos.
PIERCE:
How about little albinos?
Has the potential to be
a uniquely Greendale experience.
My lady?
♪ Please, please ♪
My lord.
♪ Please, do not go ♪
♪ Please, please, please
Do not go ♪
♪ Oh, please, please, please
ABED: Students, this is Abed.
TROY: And the disco spider.
Here at Greendale.
Greendale.
BOTH:
Say what?
A few quick announcements.
Number one.
All announcements will be cool,
starting right now.
Announcement number two,
butt soup.
Announcement number three,
I am not Hadji
from Jonny Quest, Jeff Winger.
On security, you gotta
start locking the dean's door
so guys like us don't get in.
MAN:
Hey.