CHANG:
As you know,
all faculty at Greendale
are required to give
extra credit
to students who organize
academically-related events
during what would otherwise
be known as our "free time."
No student
in any department
has ever exercised this option
until now.
[CHUCKLES]
Tonight, in the library,
I will be hosting
a Día de los Muertos party.
Just relax, just relax.
Día de los Muertos,
or Day of the Dead,
is sometimes referred to
as Mexican Halloween.
Which is quite offensive
to people
familiar with Mexican Halloween
as a sexual position.
At any rate, if you show up,
you get extra credit.
Me, I don't even get paid.
See you tonight.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
[ALL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Um...
Most of you responded
to my e-vite,
but some of you
remain evasive, so...
Count me in.
This is my first college party.
I got some tequila,
and I just rented Van Wilder 2:
the Rise of Taj, and look.
You took off your wedding ring.
My husband's been gone
for six months.
I think it's time for me
to embrace being single.
Message received.
I'm waiting to hear
from Jeff and Pierce.
I thought I shot you a response
from this pocket phone here.
Access e-mail.
You're not going
to Annie's party?
Oh, it conflicts
with the enjoyment of my life.
I cannot figure out the voice
command part of this thing.
It's like I'm my mother.
VOICE [ON PHONE]:
Calling mother.
What?
Speaking of enjoying life,
I don't wanna beat
a dead horse,
but are you sure you don't see
anything non-platonic
ever crystallizing between us?
I'm sure.
Good. One of my professors
is really hot.
And I wanted to give you
first right of refusal.
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERPHONE]:
Hello? Pierce?
Mom?
How's school going?
Are you popular?
I am headed through a tunnel
right now.
[STAMMERING]
Wrong number.
Has that boy Jeff
stopped teasing you?
How's your Canadian girlfriend?
[THUDDING]
I saw your father's ghost
again.
He's still angry.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
The Bernoulli Distribution
is the number of successes
in a sequence of
independent yes-no experiments.
Okay. For the quiz, Monday
brush up on chapters 3 and 4.
JEFF:
Bernoulli's one of
my favorites.
Little known fact: statistics
were not his only love.
He's famous for his French sauce
used on meat and poultry.
That's béarnaise.
We may need to settle this
at a restaurant.
That's cute.
A little aggressive.
But as a busy,
confident woman of authority,
I'm attracted to men
who take charge.
Are you being sarcastic
or am I nailing it?
You were nailing it
until you had to ask.
Oh, damn it.
Starting over.
Hey, you in the skirt, date me.
I'd like to, Mr. Winger.
You're tall, you dress nice.
I've graded enough of your tests
to know I'd never feel
mentally inadequate.
Thank you.
Only problem,
I don't date students.
[♪♪♪]
JEFF:
You know, if you agree to go--
Oh. Hey. Awkward.
How small is this campus?
Bastard.
It's fine, I don't care.
It's disgusting
the way men behave.
You ever see that Katherine
Heigl movie poster,
where Gerard Butler
had that heart over his wiener?
That resonated with me.
Okay, fine. But just to repeat,
I don't care what Jeff does.
Bastard.
I'm barely a student.
I'm older than you,
I drive a Lexus.
I saw Ghost Busters
in the theater.
Look, my gums are receding.
It's uncanny
how many of my buttons
you're finding,
but I have a personal rule
about this and I stick to it.
Have a cup of coffee with me,
I can change your mind.
I know you can.
That's why you're not
getting the chance.
Ooh-hoo, ooh-hoo.
Are you coming to my party?
I'm definitely gonna try
to swing by.
Then I can mark you down
as definitely being there
from 7:00 sharp
until question mark?
Here's the thing--
No, here's the thing.
I am putting my foot down,
do you understand?
I am being assertive,
and I am making eye contact,
and it is achieving results.
Are you trying to get
formidable with me?
It worked on Pierce.
Infomercials work on Pierce.
Jeff, you're the cool guy, okay?
If you show up, it will be
the first party I host
where everyone doesn't say
they need to get home in time
for the news.
[SOBBING]
This won't work.
The last time you did this,
I saved a vial of your tears.
And I've been slowly
building up an immunity.
I was so unpopular
in high school,
the crossing guard
used to lure me into traffic.
This party is a second chance
at being hip, cool,
laid-back.
Look, I will come to your party.
Thank you.
I'm putting you down
for two bags of ice
and a sleeve of paper cups.
[♪♪♪]
Taking a pill?
Yes, I am.
"Xenolovaden."
My grandpa took that
around your age.
Fantastic.
Helped him
with his going problem.
By the time Grandpa
got up in years,
his memory wasn't great.
He'd mix the wrong pills.
You know how old people are.
Heard stories about it.
One time he ran down the street
with no pants on,
which in the Gaza Strip
is considered a real party foul
so you should probably
be careful.
Look, I really don't need
your advice,
and I'm not your pantsless
grandpa.
"Pantsless grandpa."
[LAUGHS]
[FOLK MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
ANNIE:
Scary.
You look great.
Hi.
Britta,
you look adorable.
Thank you.
I hate when women use Halloween
as an excuse
to dress up like sluts,
you know?
Yeah.
Okay, everyone.
I think we can begin.
I've got everyone's
personalized cookie tombstones,
por tradición.
And, in a few minutes
we're going to start
the Dance of the Dead,
La Danza de los Muertos.
You don't have to keep
doing that.
Party on.
Nice of you to be here,
I'm sure you'd rather be out
with your hot professor.
It's funny.
I enrolled as a selfish loner.
But you and the group have given
me a crash course in friendship.
She blew you off, huh?
She's grading papers.
CHANG:
Professor Slater?
She's not grading papers.
She's at the faculty party.
Oh, look.
It's the eavesdropping matador.
Are you saying
my people are sneaky?
What?
[IN DEEP HUSKY VOICE]
There is a storm building
on the horizon.
You and I will save the night.
Chex mix, pretzels, carrots.
Predictable but appetizing.
Hey. Can I ask you something
I always wanted to ask
the real Batman?
Yeah.
Am I good-looking?
You're a very attractive
young man.
I knew it.
Let's get this party started.
BRITTA:
Who are you?
I am the Beastmaster.
From the movie, Beastmaster.
What rock
have you been living under?
What are you going as?
A gay douche bag?
Just kidding.
Nice one.
I'm not much of a costume guy.
You're not much of
a liking-ladies guy either.
Oh. Body blow.
Is that liquor?
[IN ENGLISH ACCENT]
Hello.
Here's your drinks, mates.
JEFF:
Oh. Thanks, Urkel.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I'm Harry Potter.
Really?
What up, Urkel?
[♪♪♪]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
Hey.
Oh!
All right.
What are you taking?
Huh? Oh.
You know,
the usual cool stuff.
I've got 'ludes, dreamers,
Johnny Boys.
Tell you what, I'll trade you
one of mine for two of yours.
I don't know,
Star-Burns, I'm--
Sorry, I thought I was dealing
with the Beastmaster.
Hey. Who said you weren't?
Saddle up, fruit pie.
Don't mind if I do.
May I?
Here, take this.
Give anyone that shows up
their stupid credit.
You going to the faculty party?
Make me your plus one.
Give it up, Winger.
Professor Slater
doesn't date students.
Or married Asians
who drive mopeds.
I'll give you 20 bucks.
I'll bring the hog around.
Okay, it's time
for the Dance of the Dead.
Everyone form a circle.
Lights. Music.
Is it under genre
or on a specific play list?
Hey, man,
what'd you slip me?
I keep grinding my teeth
and I wanna kiss everybody.
What did you slip me, man?
My heart stopped racing
and I can't pee.
Now, for the first dance,
I would like to invite a very
special guest to the floor.
Jeff Winger?
[FOLK MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Jeff?
Where's Jeff?
Please slow down.
Please.
CHANG: Stop crying, Winger.
JEFF:
Watch it!
Is Jeff gone?
You know, I'm gonna go.
I don't wanna miss the news.
News.
He just stepped out.
He's gonna be right back.
He's going to
the faculty party.
To be with Professor
Short Skirt? We hate her.
No, it's not about her,
Shirley.
I can't believe that Jeff
would do this to Annie.
Yes, absolutely,
it's about Annie.
We should go find
that bitch's car
and snap off her antenna.
It's like high school
all over again.
Everyone's leaving.
Not me.
I can do this all night.
I love you.
[CHATTERING]
[BIG-BAND MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
There you go, pretty lady.
What are you doing here?
Showing you my non-student side.
I have to admit,
this outfit is doing it for me.
I may or may not
have been deflowered
by a junior rodeo champion.
You remind me
of my first time too.
You lost your virginity
to Robin Hood?
No, with an attractive woman
at a party.
We seem destined
to repeat history.
I told you, no students.
It's unseemly.
I go out with you,
you tell your friends.
What friends?
I have no friends.
I hate everyone here
but you.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
You should be over
at the library with Annie.
Whoa. Yippee ki-yay.
Thought you weren't
a costume guy.
Had to have one to get in,
squirrel.
Oh. So where did you get it?
I wouldn't think any costume
stores would be open this late.
I don't know
what you're getting at.
The words you're looking for
are, "I own a cowboy outfit."
And it is tight too.
Did you buy it like that?
Your toy gun to my head,
I'd say yes.
Hi, Michelle Slater, PhD.
Britta Perry, GED.
Oh, are you a classmate
of Jeff's?
When you say classmate,
it sounds like
we take naps together
and eat paste.
What's great about
community college is
is that a lot of the students
are as mature as the teachers.
Jeff, you must return
to Annie's party.
She's feeling unpopular.
Jeff, Pierce took something
and he is tripping balls.
He's touching people
and dancing weird.
It's like Grumpy Old Men,
but not hilarious.
Okay. Guys, I'm at a grown-up
Halloween party, all right?
You're all being unseemly.
Oh, no.
How are we unseemly?
Why is Urkel ripping
the antenna
off Professor Slater's car?
[CROWD GASPS]
That's right,
Professor Slim Calves.
This is what you get when
you steal Jeff
from a good woman.
[CROWD GASPS]
No, Abed.
[LAUGHING]
[PIERCE MUMBLING
INDISTINCTLY]
[MEOWING]
Is he meowing?
Yeah.
Enough.
I want you guys out of here.
Britta, I don't care about
your high school soap opera.
Abed, you're not Batman.
Pierce, Pierce, Pierce.
Stop grinding on the Women's
Studies department.
You are too old to be tripping.
I'm old?
What do you mean old?
Whose hands are these?
[GROANING]
Stop me.
Way to go.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I know I'm not Batman.
You could try not being a jerk.
She's pretty hot.
Well, where were we,
little doggie?
Unseemly.
Yeah, crap.
[THUDDING
AND GLASS BREAKING]
BRITTA:
Shirley?
[GRUNTING]
This is Professor
Robin Hood's office.
What are you doing?
Putting this hose in her desk.
You turn the water on.
Why?
To teach that long neck,
weave-having bank teller
she can't steal another
woman's man, that's why.
Uh...
I have a confession to make.
I think some
of what I just said
may have more to do
with my situation.
Yeah, the long neck,
weave-having bank teller
didn't feel universal.
My ex-husband
came by this morning,
and he asked
for his ring back.
It was his mother's,
and he wants to give it
to his new girlfriend.
Shirley, that sucks.
The best thing that ever
happened to me was him leaving.
I just always thought
he'd come crawling back,
and I'd get to tell him
to go to hell.
[CRYING]
He couldn't even
give me that.
You know what the crazy
thing is?
Everything you've done tonight?
It's like I was too proud
to admit I was hurt,
so I had to pretend
that you were.
I totally get that.
I feel better now.
Let's go check on Annie.
Can you believe
I targeted this poor lady?
Look at all these awards,
I bet she's nice.
BRITTA:
Yeah.
Nice and pretentious.
[DISTORTED FOLK MUSIC
PLAYING]
Pierce, are you okay?
[LAUGHING
IN DISTORTED VOICE]
Hey, man, what's going on?
You have a full-on erection.
Just relax. Relax, man.
Just relax, okay?
JEFF:
You are too old to be tripping.
SKULL [IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]:
You're going to die.
JEFF:
You are too old to be tripping.
Tell me about The Beatles,
Pierce.
Tell me about Woodstock
and sputnik, Pierce.
[YELLS]
[LAUGHING]
[CRYING]
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Do I feel a breeze here?
Because someone
just struck out.
She blew you off too,
Chang.
Is that what you have
to fall back on?
Look at me, bro.
Look at me.
I've got the body
of a fifth grader, okay?
If I was working
with what you've got,
she'd be at the Comfort Inn
right now
giving me
a Mexican Halloween.
It's this campus.
It feeds on my coolness.
I got no moves anymore.
Moves?
Everything's a game
to guys like you.
I know one move I bet
you've never tried in your life.
What is it?
Please sleep with me.
Please.
Pretty please.
I'm so lonely.
I haven't slept with anyone
in a very long time,
and you're so good-looking.
Please do me the favor
of having sex with me.
Okay. Stay three steps behind
and promise
you won't tell anybody.
I promise. I promise.
PIERCE:
Everybody stay out
of the library.
Pierce, it's okay.
Come out of there.
PIERCE:
No, I'm not ready to die.
BRITTA:
You're not gonna die.
Look at me.
Just keep walking.
Don't make eye contact.
Jeff, Jeff, Jeff.
Pierce is freaking out.
You're the only one
that can help.
What makes you think that?
PIERCE: Is Jeff there?
He's the only one who can help.
He says he's gonna kill himself
but doesn't want us to call 911
because he doesn't wanna get
in trouble for taking drugs.
I can't believe
I'm doing this.
I, uh...
I think I have to say
good night.
Are you, like, a court appointed
guardian for these people?
No. Um...
They're my classmates.
Good night, Jeff.
CHANG:
Loser!
[♪♪♪]
What in the Pink Floyd?
PIERCE:
I'm gonna crush myself to death
with desks and tables, Jeff.
Is that a death
befitting a beastmaster?
PIERCE:
I never saw Beastmaster,
I just wanted to be cool.
I'm coming in there, Pierce.
[♪♪♪]
[DESKS AND CHAIRS CREAKING]
Those floating Mexican
skeletons were right.
My life is over.
Well, when we go to floating
skeletons with our problems,
we get what we pay for,
don't we?
I'm old, Jeff.
Pierce, I don't know how
you spent the first 60 years,
but I know
in the last two months,
you've probably doubled
the national average
for amount of life lived
per lifetime.
Well, I do have a young
African-American friend.
Yeah, and more importantly,
you're dressed like a gladiator
in a desk fort that you built
during a bad trip.
If life is just a series
of ridiculous attempts
to be alive,
you're a hero to everything
that's ever lived.
Yeah?
Yeah.
[RUMBLING]
[ALL GASP]
[♪♪♪]
Batman?
[IN DEEP HUSKY VOICE]
Yeah.
Are you staying
for the party?
If I stay,
there can be no party.
I must be out there
in the night,
staying vigilant.
Wherever a party needs
to be saved, I'm there.
Wherever there are masks,
wherever there's tomfoolery
and joy,
I'm there.
But sometimes I'm not
because I'm out in the night,
staying vigilant, watching.
Lurking, running, jumping,
hurdling, sleeping.
No, I can't sleep.
You sleep. I'm awake.
I don't sleep, I don't blink.
Am I a bird? No.
I'm a bat.
I am Batman.
Or am I?
Yes, I am Batman.
Happy Halloween.
[IMITATING YODA]
I'm Batman.
You sound like Cookie Monster.
[IN DEEP VOICE] I'm Batman.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
That's Batman.
Candy corn
looks like tiny traffic cones.
Yeah, it sure does.
At, like, a candy
traffic school.
Like a little gingerbread man
at the wheel, and he's drunk.
Look out.
We driving.
Yeah, but you keep wanting
to eat yourself.
All day.
That's one of my biggest fears.
What is?
If I ever, like,
woke up as a doughnut.
You would eat yourself.
I wouldn't even question it.
Mm. That would be tasty.
It's cool to know other people
think about this stuff too.
Yeah.