From now on, we'll refer to each
other by our Spanish nombres.
There will be--
What's this?
It's okay, it's okay.
Do it.
[LAUGHS]
Buenos dias, Winger.
Ah. Class dismissed.
[♪♪♪]
TROY:
Hey.
Shirley, look.
I'm Annie's backpack.
Stop it, Troy.
Annie, say there are two friends
and they're in the same class,
and one of them wants to ask
the other one out on a date.
Like a grownup date,
but within biking distance
of his parents' house.
Well, they could do
something on campus.
Tomorrow, there's a picnic
with live music
on the east lawn.
They're calling it
A Night Under The Stars.
Cool. I bet Randi would
love that type of thing.
Randi?
Oh, I thought--
Oh. You thought--
I can't believe I misled you
like that.
Listen...
Randi can be the name
of a guy or a girl.
And in this case,
it is definitely a girl.
Thanks for your help.
You're welcome.
And I hate you.
And I wanna have
your children.
Damn, I picked the wrong
couple to follow this morning.
Jeff and Britta are dead air.
Are you okay?
It looks like you have actual
bed head this morning.
In fashion, I'm what's known
as a tastemaker.
And you missed an entire side
of your face shaving.
And next month,
so will Gwen Stefani.
Here comes Vaughn. Bye.
Oh, crap.
Vaughn? Vaughn.
Oh, the guy with tiny nipples
you did it with.
Oh, God.
Hi, Vaughn.
Can we talk sometime?
I'm sorry
about how things ended.
Well, I'm sorry
I can't accept your apology
because you're toxic,
Britta.
You know what?
You're like the exact opposite
of an antioxidant.
Yeah.
I got band practice.
Lates.
Can't we still be friends?
Isn't the word "later"
already short enough?
Let me talk to him for you.
It'll be better
if it's man-to-man.
We won't be thinking
about our chubby thighs
or whether or not
we can have babies.
Don't talk to Vaughn.
Your hormones
are clouding your--
Don't talk to Vaughn.
That is girl
for "talk to Vaughn."
[♪♪♪]
Ooh.
Sure you don't want
a piece of that?
Shirley.
What is he doing?
Oh, I know exactly
what he's doing.
My ex-husband spent
four weeks doing that
after his innocent mistake
of calling me Valerie.
That boy is living in his car.
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
I lived in my car for a stretch
in the '70s.
Nothing like bedding a woman
on the vinyl back seat
of a Skylark.
Of course,
we didn't have the same
safety standards
back then, so...
[WHISPERS]
No condoms.
I tell you, before AIDS,
sex was like shaking hands.
Hence, AIDS.
Oh, Brittles,
I forgot to tell you.
I went and talked to Vaughn.
What?
Bad news is I could not patch up
things between you.
You really
did a number on him.
Good news is, I'm the new
keyboardist in his band.
I asked you not to talk to him
and you completely ignored me.
Hey, Tiny, you're missing the
headline. I'm in a rock band.
I'd like to be there
when the band finds out.
Oh, hi, Jeff.
We were just talking
about how in today's economy--
Mm-mm! Living in your car.
You are living in your car.
Sorry, I'm not good
at being coy.
I'm not living in my car.
I'm just sleeping in it
for a couple of days
while I work out some problems
with my condo.
It's a very temporary issue.
Gotta pay some meaningless fees.
They'll put my locks back
on the door and that'll be that.
How are you gonna
get the money?
Believe me, kitten,
Winger's got moves.
Jeff, do you need
a place to stay?
I'd offer, but my dad's
kind of racist.
Stay with me in the dorms.
My room has a bunk bed.
A misnomer,
because it's the real deal.
The next person that offers me
charity or pity
will be mentioned by name
in my suicide note.
Oh.
Annie, Annie,
thanks for your advice
about A Night Under the Stars.
Of course.
Anytime, ever.
Now I've just gotta figure out
what to bring to the picnic.
This is my first college girl,
so I really wanna impress her.
Would you mind helping me
shop for this stuff?
I'd love to.
Really?
Sure.
No.
Thanks. Later.
Bye.
Hey.
Hey. Wanna see my place?
I can see it from here.
Two girls are making out.
No, my real place.
Look at that.
The condo board's
trying to bluff me
by listing my place
as available.
But look at those faucets.
Handcrafted in Italy.
One hundred percent expensive.
Those faucets are beautiful.
You know what they would
go great with? A home.
Which you no longer have.
You need to move on
with your life.
Move on with my life?
Shmove shmon shmith shmy shfime.
This condo is all
that's left of me.
Every part of it
is a part of who I am.
Is that a bidet?
That part's for resale
value.
And Saturday afternoons.
You know,
downgrading your lifestyle
is your chance
to grow as a person.
Maybe even become one.
You know, the less you have,
the more you can be.
You know what I'm saying?
There's a silver lining here,
isn't there?
You're attracted to bums.
Good night.
Come on.
Why don't you have dinner
at my place?
I got a hotplate that plugs
into a cigarette lighter.
Yeah, but your kitchen's
being towed.
Stop!
That's my house!
Can I live with you?
Yeah, cool.
Do you want top bunk
or bottom bunk?
Top.
Me too.
Race you for it.
I win.
Look, I really need
to liquidate some assets.
It's an emergency
situation.
What kind of offer is that?
These are mint-condition issues.
I mean, the premise alone
is priceless.
The guy has the powers
and strength of a spider.
No, your incredulity
perplexes me, nerd.
Did I say anything in my sleep
about farm animals
or Brian Williams?
I don't think so.
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
Lucky Charms?
How are you so satisfied
all the time, Abed?
I mean, don't you ever want
anything more out of life
than cereal?
Sometimes I pour hot cocoa mix
into cold milk
and drink it like
a cold hot chocolate.
I call it special drink.
Someday you will know it
by its true name, diabetes.
You're Goldie Hawn, Jeff.
I'm sorry?
You're Goldie Hawn.
Is it the lips?
No.
In Overboard,
she was just like you.
Wealthy, assertive, arrogant,
got manicures all the time.
Then she fell off her boat
and it was good for her.
Ultimately, she realized
she was happier poor,
raising unruly boys
with Kurt Russell.
Can I not be Kurt Russell?
Do whatever you want.
You just have to know
what that is.
For me, it's Lucky Charms
and TV.
I could use a break.
A picnic blanket.
Genius. I was gonna
lay down newspaper.
It's the blanket my grandmother
used to court my grandfather.
Yeah?
That's pretty hot.
Thanks.
Oh.
Tell that boy how you feel.
It's scary.
If he's not interested,
I could lose the friendship too.
You could.
Love is a gamble always,
but waiting won't change
the dice.
You either roll them
or you lose your turn.
I'm going to roll them.
I am.
I just-- I need
a few more shakes.
Mm. Shake them
in your mind, okay?
If you'll excuse me,
Pierce's band is playing.
And I wanna record
the train wreck.
Kind of hoping for
a Michael Richards situation.
VAUGHN:
This is for you.
Oh, they're pretty good.
This isn't weird for you?
No.
Wanna show Vaughn some support
to help smooth things over.
♪ Saying goodbye to Britta
Was the hardest thing to do ♪
♪ But when someone's a bitch
And a liar ♪
♪ There ain't nothing left
To woo ♪
♪ I'm getting rid of Britta ♪
♪ What am I doing?
I'm getting rid of the B ♪
♪ She's a no-good B ♪
VAUGHN:
♪ I'm getting rid of Britta ♪
♪ I'm getting rid of the B ♪
♪ She's a GDB ♪
VAUGHN:
Take it, Pierce.
Same as a 45-year-old,
except he doesn't
get as tired.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING ON TV]
We can pick them
from the cream...
Great to have somebody
to watch stuff with.
My dad never wanted
to watch anything,
so I was raised by TV.
TV's the best dad there is.
TV never came home drunk.
TV never forgot me
at the zoo.
TV never abused
and insulted me.
Unless you count
Cop Rock.
That sounds cool.
Doesn't it?
Hey.
Wow.
You guys are really
dorming it up in here, huh?
Yeah. In the last two days,
I've spent a quarter.
We're having the time
of our lives.
See?
Who needs platinum faucets?
Do you guys even have
faucets in here?
There's a communal bathroom
down the hallway.
It actually helped me come
to terms with losing my condo.
You don't sit on a toilet
like that
until you've left
the material world behind.
BOTH: Pavel!
Hey, bros.
This is Pavel.
He lives next door.
He's from Poland.
[SPEAKS IN POLISH]
Britta?
♪ I'm getting rid of Britta ♪
♪ Getting rid of the B ♪
Excuse me. I have a future
murder victim to visit.
Cool.
Sorry?
[SPEAKS IN POLISH]
[BAND PLAYING]
Guys, what the hell?
"Getting Rid of Britta"?
That song was disrespectful
to me
and to the definition
of rhyme scheme.
Wow. If you don't
like my song,
you don't have to listen,
all right?
I'm an artist
and I write what I feel.
And I feel that you suck.
PIERCE: Oh, oh.
All right, hold on, Vaughn.
Can I have a word with you?
Could you come here, please,
for a second?
What did you just say to her?
I know Britta's your friend,
but my song is more important.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Your song?
We wrote it together.
Are you trying
to Garfunkel me?
Maybe, assuming
to Garfunkel someone
is to
keep putting up with them
even though
they're a fat, lazy cat
who hogs the spotlight
and eats all the lasagna.
I get it.
You're jealous of me.
What? Why?
Maybe because when I put on
these skinny jeans,
my ass looks like
a baby pumpkin.
Or maybe because I'm not
a small-nippled,
credit-hogging jag
who only knows
three power chords.
My band, my song.
You want that, huh, Pierce?
How do you like that?
I'm out!
You get on that horse.
VAUGHN:
Lates!
Pierce, did you just defend
my honor?
Huh?
Oh, yeah. Totally.
You'll light the candles
and you'll take a bite
and she'll take a bite
and you'll laugh.
[LAUGHS]
And you'll offer her
your letter jacket
dafter you notice this funny way
she shakes when she gets cold.
And she'll feel like
the luckiest girl in the world.
Right.
I couldn't have done this
without your help.
You're really nice.
We should've hung out more
in high school.
Remember when you pretended
to be my backpack?
Oh. Yeah, yeah.
I'm funny.
All right. Ah.
I gotta go get ready.
Troy, wait.
I have to tell you.
My appendix is bursting.
What?
Yeah. Yeah.
My appendix is bursting.
[SCREAMS]
Oh. Oh, no.
Okay, two young students.
I think I've been
to this dance before.
You guys are sexual partners,
right?
[LAUGHS]
Us? No.
No, he's my very good friend,
and I have appendicitis.
Oh.
Thanks for bringing me here.
Guess I ruined your date, huh?
Okay.
Doesn't seem to be
anything wrong with you.
Cool. I'll see you.
[SCREAMS]
God. Where does it hurt?
Everywhere.
We have to quarantine you.
We gotta get you
to a safe distance.
My date's on the east lawn.
East lawn, perfect.
Great.
Wait, wait.
This is a date?
Yeah, you need these.
Nice.
I'll be thinking of you.
Okay, I need to go.
No, we--
We have to observe you
overnight. It's policy.
We don't want another
Vanessa Parsons on our hands.
She was the Typhoid Mary
of herpes.
I'm kind of the Hawkeye
around here,
so it's kind of a--
Are you seeing anybody?
You guys weren't
in Spanish class.
Knight Rider
marathon.
The shadowy flight
into the world of a man
who does not exist.
[MUMBLING]
Britta, may I have a word?
Has this always been here?
You need to take Jeff back.
Never had him,
don't want him, especially now.
He's got a real
Phil Spector vibe going.
ABED:
He's like E.T.
He crashed in my place
and we're friends now,
which is great for me,
but bad for him.
He needs to get back.
What am I supposed to do?
Use your lady parts.
Abed.
Don't be naive.
The charge between you two
is keeping him going.
Tell him you'll make love to him
if he takes a shower
and finds a nice place to live.
I'm heading back.
Pavel's making babka.
Do it, Britta.
Seduce him.
Draw the tapeworm of Jeff's
old self out with the milk
that is your sexuality.
No.
Then say goodbye to E.T.
Abed, it's open.
LOUISE JEFFERSON [ON TV]:
And your wife is married
to an idiot.
What's wrong now, woman?
LOUISE:
You.
You can't see further
than them--
What are you doing?
That was The Jeffersons, honky.
I was wrong, okay?
Material possessions
are important.
Think how much happier
the Jeffersons were
than that family on Good Times.
Yeah, but they had good times.
Do good times really matter?
What about good cars,
good lobster?
What about that sport
where the British people
ride the horses
with the really long hammers?
Jeez, you are way out
of your element here.
Yes, and I do not believe
a single word
I am saying for me.
But for you?
Maybe you're one of those
rare people
with nothing underneath
the surface.
Maybe if you put stain remover
on a turd,
you don't get a diamond.
You just get a turd
with less direction in life.
Thanks, coach.
Can you turn the TV back on?
[GROANS]
Faucets.
Italian faucets. Handcrafted.
These look like--
Wait.
I made this notch
to indicate
optimal cleansing temperature
for combination skin.
These were mine?
For a fancy condo,
you've got awful security.
Install those in a new apartment
so that every day,
when you're spending way
too much time on your hair,
you can look down and think:
"I was a huge phony before.
I can do it again."
Yeah.
You're into me.
I beg your unbelievable pardon?
Look at all this work
you're doing
just to have me around again.
You were more attracted to me
than you were willing to admit.
I was doing this all for Abed.
You are the worst.
Yeah, clearly.
Sorry. Ahem.
I want you to know
I haven't changed my mind
about the band.
I'm out.
MAN:
We wanna recognize
a couple of sponsors.
First off is Anderson Septic.
Also, do me a favor, will you?
Lay off Britta.
I mean, she may walk
like she just got off a horse,
but underneath all that clown
makeup, she's a good kid.
Mm-hm. No worries, man.
I've moved on.
Lates.
Lates, okay.
Snakes. What--?
Greendale!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BAND PLAYING]
♪ Pierce, I don't need you
In my band ♪
♪ I don't need your heart
Or your hand ♪
♪ I am my own person ♪
♪ And, Pierce, you're a B ♪
Yeah, you heard me say it.
♪ Pierce, you're a B ♪
ANNIE:
No!
Before you two proceed,
I have one thing to say.
Did you say it already?
I want my nana's
blanket back.
Do you guys mind?
Could you scoot over?
It's an heirloom.
I want it.
Thank you.
Have a nice date.
I don't care what you think.
For me, that was huge.
I know, sweetie.
Let's go find you some pants.
Okay?
Yeah, cool, thanks.
♪ This a song for Pierce
'Cause him so old ♪
♪ His body made
Of wrinkles and folds ♪
♪ Stupid and ugly
He smells like a fart ♪
♪ Poo-poo in his pants
And poo-poo in my heart ♪
Hey, look what the cat
dragged out and licked clean.
I saw how much
you missed me,
and smelled what happens
to Pavel on cabbage night,
and realized the world
was better off with me in it.
Thanks.
For caring.
Hey.
You looked like
you moved out.
I checked into a motel
and I'm looking for apartments.
You would've been fine
with me staying forever?
Yup.
You're pretty cool, Abed.
You're a huge nerd.
Thanks.
ALL:
♪ Pierce, Pierce, Pierce ♪
♪ Pierce, you're a B ♪
I'm Pierce.
Yeah, song's about me.
♪ Pierce, Pierce, Pierce
Pierce, you're a B ♪
WOMAN: Yeah!
MAN 1: Yeah!
VAUGHN:
Come on, sing it for me.
ALL:
♪ Pierce, Pierce, Pierce ♪
♪ Pierce, you're a B ♪
MAN 2:
Yeah, he is.
ALL:
♪ Pierce, Pierce, Pierce ♪
♪ Pierce, you're a B ♪
VAUGHN:
Ow!
We are Some Worries!
Good night, Greendale!
♪ East side, west side
North side, south ♪
♪ Vaughn's breath is so bad
His butt's mad at his mouth ♪
♪ This rap is by Pierce
Vaughn is dumb ♪
♪ He wears diapers to bed
And sucks his mother's thumb ♪
♪ And when he wakes up stupid
Wishing he was me ♪
♪ He has a big poop breakfast
With a glass of pee ♪
♪ Then he goes to school
Where he's stupid again ♪
♪ And everybody hates him
Even all his friends ♪
♪ When you come after Pierce
Then the battle is on ♪
♪ So this rap goes out
To stupid Vaughn ♪
Uh-huh. Well played, Pierce.
This isn't over.
[HIP-HOP BEAT
PLAYING OVER KEYBOARD]