So then the guy says
to the housekeeper:
"Make sure she's dead."
Stop me if you've heard this.
Would've been nice
27 minutes ago.
The housekeeper says,
"We don't have a pool."
And the guy says--
PELTON: Good morning, Greendale.
Just a reminder,
our debate team will bring home
the championship tomorrow
versus City College.
Go, Human Beings.
Great, now I gotta start
the whole joke over again.
Okay, so this--
No! I've got one for you.
A doddering old fool
walks into a bar,
tells a stupid joke,
and I crush his windpipe
with my three-ringed binder.
I don't get it.
Britta's giving up cigarettes.
Don't tell. I'll slap that look
off your pointy face.
I'm saying this because I care
and you're my friend.
You need to start smoking again.
I think you should.
You lose weight,
your skin looks great.
I appreciate your support,
but I've got to quit.
You thought
about hypnotherapy?
I know a hypnotherapist.
Ten-to-one says it's him.
His name is Pierce Hawthorne.
And I'm very effective.
Can you help me
block out people's voices
I find extremely annoying?
Jeff, she's right there.
Pierce,
I would be grateful
for your help.
You would? Super.
I'll set it up.
What? I feel bad for him.
Plus, I just yelled at him.
You yelled at me too.
Oh.
Did I hurt your feelings?
Wow. Wow.
Have you seen
the film department's website?
What do you think?
All of Abed's films
are about us.
What?
TROY: Check it out.
[ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYS]
What else is new?
ALL: Jeff.
Hola.
Jeff, stop being so relaxed.
We need to talk to you about--
You're living out of your car.
Why are you living
out of your car?
Those people look just like us.
That's eerie.
Fine, it's true.
I'm living out of my car.
And I don't want anyone's help.
We had that
exact conversation last week.
But Abed posted
this video two weeks ago.
That boy is a soothsayer.
This is wrinkling my brain.
That's wrinkling my brain.
Get a load of these wrinkles.
Who's that old guy?
Hi. I'm Pierce Hawthorne.
Oh, come on.
[THE 88'S
"AT LEAST IT WAS HERE" PLAYS]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
There he is.
Oh, Mr. Winger, hold on.
Did you hear my announcement?
I hang on every word.
I assume that's sarcasm.
Correct.
You didn't hear?
I'm barely listening now.
Oh, okay.
My debate partner dropped out.
We need you for championship.
Jeffrey, as debate coach,
I'm offering you an opportunity
to spend a night
drinking from the cup of life
rather than romancing
your nether regions.
Who better than a former lawyer
to really stick it
to those City College snobs
and their star debater Simmons?
Mmm. Pass.
Okay, no, no, no. Wait.
Okay, no, no, no. Look.
Listen, jerk wad.
I'm sorry, that got heated.
Greendale needs a win.
The best compliment
our sports program gets
is our basketball team
is gay.
So, what's it gonna take?
A plum parking space?
Free meals?
A night of companionship,
if you know what I mean?
I'll do it
for the parking space.
If you promise
not to tell me what you mean.
WHITMAN: All right. Yeah.
Pierce, thank you.
I appreciate you
helping me out.
And I appreciate
the opportunity.
Sometimes I think
people don't take me seriously.
What are you gonna do?
Wave a pocket watch
in front of my face
and tell me
I'm getting very sleepy.
No. Just checking the time.
[WATCH CLATTERS]
Close your eyes,
keep them closed.
And listen to the soothing
sound of my voice.
The only word
that will bring you out is
"gorilla."
Okay, now, focus on the rhythm
of your own breathing.
[♪♪♪]
And when you feel the desire
to light up a cigarette
you will associate these urges
with things that disgust you.
Bad tasting food,
sex with men,
wearing attractive clothing,
and--
Oh, God,
I think I really hurt myself.
Somebody help me.
Oh! Britta, wake up.
Why did I put you under so well?
Damn my talents. Aah!
The topic for the debate is,
"Are people inherently good
or evil?"
When do you want
to get together to strategize?
Annie, I was a lawyer.
I was a debater for money.
I think I can handle this.
How was hypnotherapy?
He fell down, screamed,
I laid with eyes closed
to make him feel
like a good hypnotherapist.
This will never end.
It's already done.
He just wants one more session.
♪ Wah-waah ♪
Where's Abed? Need to talk
about his films.
He is prescient.
He can read minds.
[BOTH GASP]
I know what you'll say.
Watched my movies?
He's a witch.
Get him.
Not a witch, a student
of human character.
I know you guys all so well
I can predict your behavior.
Like, Shirley,
I know you're a sweet,
Christian, generous person.
Oh, that's nice.
I know you have rage issues.
Careful, boy. Oh!
Careful, boy.
ABED:
Here, check this out.
May I?
Yeah.
Jeff's character acts
like nothing affects him.
Things bother him
more than he lets on.
I'm top of the class.
Gaah!
He's also very vain.
Ridiculous.
ALL:
Ohh.
[TROY'S CHARACTER CRYING]
Why am I crying? Will I listen
to "Come Sail Away" by Styx?
Don't worry, it's just a movie.
I can't predict the future.
I hurt my leg. Ah!
[♪♪♪]
What up, happy people?
You tell me my future right now,
evil wizard.
I think your shirt's trying
to get out of your pants.
As Golding's Lord of the Flies
demonstrates, man,
when left to his own devices,
will descend
into chaos and evil.
And now, from City College,
Jeremy Simmons.
[CHEERING]
STUDENTS [CHANTING]:
Jeremy. Jeremy.
There were 23,000
kidney donations
in America last year.
Man is good.
The average life expectancy
for a man in a community
is 23 years longer
than a man alone.
Man is good.
And just 10 minutes ago,
a bald, bespectacled man
held the door
for a man in a wheelchair.
Man is good.
Oh. I hate this guy.
By the end of this debate
I will prove
with facts and data
that man is inherently good.
[CHEERING]
Little trick for achieving
the competitive mind set.
I always envision my opponent
having aggressive sex
with my mother.
JEFF:
This feels so formal.
Let's just talk.
People are evil.
They can't help it.
I didn't catch your name.
It's Jean.
Take Jean here.
She spent a lot of time
this morning
making herself look so lovely.
Tell me, how many people
told you how great you look?
None.
Man is evil.
JEAN:
But you just said
how great I looked.
For my own selfish purposes.
The fact is,
as hot as you look
and it is quite hot,
I wouldn't have said anything.
When I talk about people
being evil,
I could cite quotes
or dig up statistics,
but those are just words
and numbers.
I think we could have
a little more fun
if I express myself in song.
ALL:
♪ Evil woman ♪
That's my time, everybody.
Thank you very much. Yeah.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
At the end of round one.
City College, 50.
Greendale, eight.
[♪♪♪]
JEFF:
I got eight?
I only got eight?
She got eight.
You got zero.
It's debate, not American Idol.
Nice work, L.A. Law.
All sizzle, no steak.
I don't care, dude.
I'm doing this
for a parking space.
MAN:
Let's go, boys.
I wanna see some hustlers.
By Zeus.
What sort of jackassery is this?
We're in the middle of a debate.
We reserved the gym
for practice so...
Yup, they reserved it.
Okay,
they got us by the short ones.
The debate is suspended
until tomorrow.
Hopefully, by then
we can get our act together.
COACH:
Oh, great try, Bruce. Great try.
When are we getting together
to prepare for tomorrow?
Never. Because it's stupid
and I don't care.
Bite me.
Maybe Simmons is right.
You really are all sizzle
and no steak.
You probably couldn't beat him.
What do you mean?
We are going to study harder
and beat City College tomorrow.
Really?
No.
Who am I, iCarly?
Abed is right,
you act like things
don't bother you, but they do.
Six months ago
I was a lawyer, I wore suits.
I used to say stuff
like "objection" and "sidebar."
Now I'm losing
a community college debate
to Jeremy "Soul Patch" Simmons.
Hey, Winger.
You like to sing?
I like to sing too.
♪ Zero for Winger ♪
Kick that.
♪ Was a big shot lawyer ♪
♪ Now he's a loser ♪
Lay off. Jeff didn't
understand the rules.
Yeah? What's your excuse,
eight points?
Dude, leave her out of this.
♪ Little Annie Adderall
Was an outcast in high school ♪
That's it, we are gonna debate
the living crap out of you.
We've got some preparing to do.
I liked you better smoking.
I'm so sorry.
No, you're right,
my feet are long and stupid.
You can't unring that bell.
Oh, no.
That's my newspaper.
What do you need a paper for?
You knew what was gonna happen,
you Magic Eight Ball.
Pierce hurt his leg.
Britta made Troy cry.
What's my destiny?
Am I gonna die in a car?
Is it going to happen soon?
I'm just an entertainer.
But if it will make you
feel better,
here, let me show you
what I'm working on.
[SHIRLEY SCREAMING]
Were-- No. Were...
Sorry, is that me being
chased down by a werewolf?
That's how you'd behave
in that situation. No?
The situation being me
being chased by a werewolf?
Mm-hm.
And that's Jeff
locking lips with Annie?
Mm-hm. Yeah.
You're a fool.
Stanford students were divided
into prisoners and guards.
The guards immediately started--
Ugh!
What's wrong?
I have pain above my eyebrow.
It's a stress headache.
I got my first one when I was 4.
I hate it.
Get to used to it.
You're knee-deep in it.
This is debate.
If you wanna win,
you need to prepare.
Well, agreed.
But if you wanna win,
you need to loosen up.
Go off-book, robot debater.
Oh, my gosh.
You're right.
Simmons is so good
at using his inherent magnetism
to sell his points
and here I am,
like a spinster librarian
with my hair pulled back.
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
What do you think?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Be careful, Abed thinks
you two are gonna kiss.
Ha, ha, ha! Ridiculous.
Us kissing?
That is ridiculous.
Totally.
[CHUCKLES]
We should get back to work.
Yes.
Okay. The--
People are inherently evil.
Oh, we can use
this Hobbes quote.
"Man is a collection of base,
animal urges.
To act on them
and experience sinful pleasure
would be morally no different
than taking a breath."
That's poignant, right?
Yeah.
Maybe we should study alone.
Separately.
Uh-huh.
That way, we can be
more reproductive-- Productive.
Bye.
Bye. What...
Oh, you forgot your phone.
Oh, I can get another one.
The next time
you even see a cigarette,
you will think of things
that disgust you.
And while you're under so deep,
you'll find yourself attracted
to slightly older men.
Perhaps some barrel-chested stud
with just enough tummy
to love.
You'll want to buy him dinner.
Then go back to his hot tub.
You'll invite one
of your friends
to join us for a three-way.
Maybe someone
with low self-esteem
and slightly larger breasts.
Go to hell, you disgusting pig.
A-ha!
I was awake the whole time.
I was faking it.
I know. I saw you.
What do you think I am?
Some joke?
No, I was trying to make you
feel better about yourself.
How dare you pity me.
I may be a little older,
my ideas may seem weird,
my fashion sense may cause envy,
but I have a lot to offer
and I will not to be pitied.
Do not help me up.
And as German poet
Franz Wickmeyer once wrote:
"Snow falls
from the heavens pure.
We cannot blame the snow
for being soiled by the Earth."
Man is good.
What? That dude gets it.
Jeff Winger will now offer
a two-minute rebuttal.
Hey, sizzle.
What you going to sing tonight?
I'm in the mood for Sade.
Okay.
In the Stanford
Prison Experiment,
21 out of 21 students,
when given absolute power,
abused and tortured
their fellow students.
My competitor likened people
to pure falling snow.
I would respond,
"There is none righteous,
no, not one."
Now, I realize
Mr. Simmons' quote
was from
the great Franz Wickmeyer.
Mine was just from
a simple desert handyman
named Jesus.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, that's nice.
Survival of the fittest wires
an impulse to eliminate people.
Counter point.
Mother Teresa, Joan of Arc.
Rebuttal.
Nuclear bombs.
Nuclear families.
Abu Ghraib.
Apu from The Simpsons.
Double rejoinder.
Telemarketers.
Organ donors.
Hate crimes.
Executions.
Ketchup is a vegetable.
Wow. This is a real barn-burner.
Oh, God, did I just say
cross-burner?
No, you did not.
Oh, good.
We make an amazing team.
I know, we're so in sync.
We're like a perfect duet
or great se--
Professor Whitman.
Your preparation was impeccable.
You remind me of a young me
with slightly worse hair.
I just checked with the judges.
They'll need a miracle
to win in rebuttal.
Simmons is finished.
This is too much for me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
He's going off-book.
Why is he ripping the cards,
doesn't he need cards?
It's a gambit.
[♪♪♪]
[ALL GASP]
He hates me, yet he caught me.
Man is good.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Damn.
Abed. Abed.
[JEREMY TUMBLES]
He was horny,
so he dropped him.
Man is evil.
[EDWARD SHARPE
&amp; THE MAGNETIC ZEROS'
"HOME" PLAYING]
Greendale wins.
Huzzah!
Eat that, Simmons.
Whoo!
God!
That off-book enough for you?
♪ Not the way
That I do love you ♪
Simmons got robbed.
They kissed.
You do have powers.
I'm going to die by werewolf.
Shirley, I don't have powers.
Trust me.
In my next film, we discover
Pierce is an actual genius.
That's not gonna happen.
No, it's not.
Pierce,
I can't smoke a cigarette
without thinking of a three-way
in your hot tub.
You did it.
Yes.
I did?
You're a genius.
Who's the third?
You did great in there.
Let's take
this bacchanalia outside.
Full moon tonight.
Shirley. Shirley!
Well, I'm going this way, so...
Well, congratulations, buddy.
Thanks, pal.
Just pat me.
[BEAT-BOXING]
♪ Donde, está, la biblioteca ♪
♪ Me llamo T-Bone
La araña discoteca ♪
♪ Discoteca, muñeca
La biblioteca ♪
♪ Está en bigotes grandes
El perro, manteca ♪
♪ Manteca, bigotes, gigante ♪
Cut, cut.
Let me ask you a question.
Do you hate this?
Do you hate doing this?
Do you?
Can I talk to you for a second?
Just hold on.
[TROY &amp; ABED WHISPERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Just have fun with it.
Take 36.