[FEEDBACK SQUEALS]
Okay, you can hear me?
Okay. Um, good morning.
I'm here to kick off
the first day of a new tradition
at our school called Green Week.
What?
First, a month to black history,
now, seven days on the Irish.
All this week, Greendale College
is becoming so Earth-smart
that we're changing our name
to Envirodale.
But we were already
called Greendale.
[MAN LAUGHS]
WOMAN: Yeah.
MAN: Yeah.
Well, there's also going to be
a free rock and roll concert
by a certain band
called Green Day.
[STUDENTS APPLAUDING
AND CHATTERING]
That make you happy?
No, not really.
[WHISPERING]
We need to re-do these.
We printed 5000.
Well, print 5000 more.
I'm trying
to save a planet here.
[♪♪♪]
Pencils down.
[PENCIL SCRIBBLING]
[♪♪♪]
Annie.
[CHANG CLEARS THROAT]
I wasn't--
I want you all
to write a one-page essay,
in Español
entitled, "Annie's Mistake."
Why doesn't Annie have
to write it?
Okay, two pages, entitled:
"The Consequences
of Questioning Authority."
This is Spanish 101.
I know how to say "hello",
"tomorrow", "tables are female."
That's the only Spanish
you taught us.
Oh! Six pages on ignorance.
[STUDENTS WHINING]
Guys, put your hands down.
Señor Chang, please continue.
We respect your authority.
Thank you, Britta.
Twenty pages on ass kissing.
Due on Monday.
This Monday?
[THE 88'S
"AT LEAST IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
If Señor Chang
gets any crazier,
he's gonna win
one of those Grammy awards.
[LAUGHING]
I've already reported him
to the dean.
He said they've been trying
to fire him for three years
but nobody wants his job.
I can't write a 20-page paper.
I got a presentation
in Marketing class on Friday.
And public speaking gives me
the nervous sweats.
I can help you with that.
I accept.
That's how messed up
things are.
Well, we're screwed too.
We're three days behind
on a Biology lab.
The reason it's taking so long
is Troy's afraid of--
I'm not afraid, Abed.
I choose not to be around rats
because they are unpopular.
Same goes
for centipedes and lakes.
There's only one solution.
Someone has to go to Chang
and talk to him.
I vote we all look at Jeff
at the same time.
In a way,
all of you are right.
What was I tuning out?
You have to get Chang
to call off this homework.
the one
with the silver tongue.
Yeah, go tongue Chang.
What makes you think
I could convince Chang
if I can't even convince you
not to make me do it?
[MURMURING]
TROY: Jeff raises a good point.
Wait. You are convincing.
You could do it.
You want me to risk the C
that I'm pulling
in that psycho's class
by putting myself on his radar?
That guy goes any more nuts,
he's gonna win a Grammy.
[ALL LAUGH]
TROY: You are hilarious.
That's very funny.
What is it, the chair?
How do you think you're
gonna keep pulling a C
if he keeps assigning
this much work?
Because I have you guys.
Well, guess what,
handsome hobo?
Your gravy train's
leaving the station.
[IMITATING TRAIN CHUGGING]
Ignore what she's doing.
We are serious.
Fine, I'll do it.
But when you find my body,
don't believe the suicide note.
[PIANO MUSIC PLAYING
ON COMPUTER]
This better not awaken anything
in me.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Green Day is here.
Oh, wow.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, what's this about now?
We're Greene Daeye.
Okay. Oh.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
CHANG:
What do you want, Winger?
You complaining about homework
on behalf of the class?
Can I ask you a personal
question, Señor Chang?
Okay, Freud.
Sure, you try to penetrate
my psychological armor and you--
Did your wife leave you?
Holy--
How'd you know?
Well, when you pick juries,
you learn to read
the little stuff.
Same shirt twice in one week.
Teaching us the word esposa
means "liar."
A picture of you with a woman
with a Post-it note
dialogue balloon
above her head that says,
"Enjoy it while it lasts."
We met at a salsa club.
And, um,
she loved the way I danced.
But you know how it goes.
You get a job--
You stop salsa dancing.
Of course I know.
You make no mistake about this,
Winger.
I pleasured that woman greatly.
Yeah.
You look like you would have to.
I'm not surprised you said that.
[♪♪♪]
I like you, Winger.
Pickled bull testicle?
Uh, are you offering
or collecting?
♪ Mary had a little lamb ♪
♪ Little lamb
Little lamb ♪
♪ Row, row, row your boat ♪
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
Troy, sing.
The assignment is to train a rat
to respond to a song.
Yeah.
Did you have to pick a duet?
Hm?
BOTH:
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
♪ Beneath the pale moonlight ♪
He did it. Good boy, Fievel.
Commencing reward.
I have to open the cage.
You don't have to warn me,
I'm not afraid!
[SQUEALING]
[SCREAMING]
[STUDENTS LAUGHING]
Fievel.
Everybody, shut up.
I'll kick all your asses,
but you all have
to come up here.
[LAUGHS]
Dude, you are gonna be fine.
You just have to move on.
And if you hang out with me
sometime,
you will see how great
single life can be.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What about tonight?
Absolutely.
Oh, shoot.
My Spanish study group
has to get together
every night now.
You have been really letting us
have it with this homework.
I really have, haven't I?
Yeah.
Tell you what, for my new buddy,
Jeff, essay cancelled.
Shh-clacky.
Fantastic.
That is fantastic.
Everybody will be so happy.
Oh-oh-oh.
I didn't say everybody.
It's for my new friend Jeff.
You're the one
coming out with me, right?
Right. Yeah.
I suppose that will put you
in an unenviable,
uncomfortable position
and wanna be--
Your jacket. Let's do this.
Awesome, great.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Is there a rat in here?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Abed.
El Tigre.
[♪♪♪]
Well, did you talk to Chang?
Yeah, but it didn't do
any good.
My head still hurts
from the yelling.
My pupils
are more sensitive to light
because he yelled at me
so much.
Oh, well, now I feel bad
that we made you do that.
Maybe we can help
with your essay.
Oh, that's okay.
I'm working on mine by myself.
You could do my homework
next time.
See you in class.
He's hiding something.
Britta, Jeff suffered for us.
Give him a little credit.
Yeah. You can be pretty cold.
ABED: Troy?
Damn.
Here comes Abed.
He needs my help.
I gotta get out of here.
Troy? You guys seen a rat?
Troy knocked over Fievel's cage
and he escaped.
Oh, Abed, I'm sorry.
He probably found more rats
and is very happy
living with them.
Try to join the rest of us
in reality, Britta.
[♪♪♪]
I believe that, uh,
fusing brownies
with the, uh, Internet
is going to create
the next Napster for brownies.
Yawn!
Can't I just write it on cards?
No.
Do you know anybody
who reads from cards?
No.
No, you don't, and that's why.
You might consider
a darker top.
Note taken.
Oh, and don't--
Don't lock your knees.
Never lock your knees.
You know what happens
when you lock your knees?
You die.
Oh.
Second, when you wanna
drive home a point,
hand them a sandwich.
Try it.
Hand them a sandwich. See?
Hand them a sandwich.
Yeah.
Except that you're--
You just dropped
the sandwich
as opposed
to handing it to them.
Handing the palm.
Right. Yeah.
Try attention-grabbing words
to wake up the audience,
such as: multiple orgasm.
Oh, no, no. I don't think
that would fit into my message.
Maybe we should focus more on--
Whatever.
Yeah, and about
these filler words of yours.
I mean,
nobody wants to buy brownies
from somebody
that says "um" and "like."
I have a method for fixing that.
Start from the top.
Okay. Ahem.
These brownies are, uh--
Uh!
They, um--
Um!
These brownies are delicious.
They taste like--
Like.
That's not a filler word.
Whatever, valley girl.
[♪♪♪]
The difference between usted
and tu
is a matter of formality.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
You are old.
You are ugly.
No, you're not.
Shakira.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Westside!
You are dirty.
Dude.
CHANG: Still formal but plural.
Because while both are dirty,
neither are my friends. Okay?
And on another subject,
hope you guys are working hard
on your essays.
That's 30 percent of your grade.
Oh, no.
Jeff already turned
in his essay.
Great job.
Thanks.
CHANG:
As soon as you turn in
your essays on Monday,
there's gonna be a big-ass quiz,
so study hard.
Class dismissed.
Dude.
Crazy night last night, man.
That was crazy.
When you go out with me,
it gets crazy.
That's the Winger guarantee.
Dude, let's do it again.
Yeah, I want to,
it's just the quiz, you know?
Study, study.
Well, how about this:
Bling. A-plus.
Nice work, Winger.
I knew I could do it
if I applied myself.
[JEFF &amp; CHANG LAUGHING]
Cherry daiquiri.
[♪♪♪]
Uh-huh, later.
You devious clump of overpriced
fabric and hair product.
Speaking as one of meek, as soon
as I inherit Earth, you dead.
You got a weird forehead.
We're all very disappointed.
All right,
dial it back a little.
If anyone should be
disappointed, it's me.
What kind of group
threatens to kick someone out
unless he helps them?
What kind of a person
is asked to help other people
and then helps himself?
Yeah.
Helps himself?
I don't like
being talked to that way.
He's using fake outrage
to justify leaving.
Fake outrage? Justify my--?
Yeah, that's it,
I'm out of here.
Are you breaking up
with the group?
That's what you guys want.
I've been divorced
seven times.
Don't answer your phones
and bury all your money
in the backyard.
Here you go. Look at Pierce's
paragraph from unit two.
Let's see,
"I took a computer class
at Tienda De Manzana,"
the Apple Store.
Adorable.
Keep going.
"And the saleswoman
had manzanas gigantes."
Ruined it.
Imagine being married to him?
Seven times, seven different
women agreed to marry that guy.
It's crazy.
[WHIMPERING AND CRYING]
I'm so alone.
I'm so lonely,
I wanna die.
Come on, man. It--
Come on. Don't do that.
I just miss her so much.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
This is so stupid.
No, no, no,
it's fine, it's just--
Buddy, you know...
I'm dumb.
I can see that you're hurting
but I have to get to Accounting.
It's not like I'm hitting strip
clubs with Professor Whitman.
You better not be.
What?
All I ask is for you to keep
filling the void in my soul.
I'll have
to think of something.
Let me rest gently
on your pecs.
Best closer to a presentation,
a Nicholson quote.
You take a phrase
from one of his films
and you tailor it
to your product.
You can't handle
a moist towelette.
Something like that,
you know.
But you can't use that one.
That's mine.
Thanks, Pierce.
I'm gonna write it on cards.
Okay.
Just don't let anybody know
I was involved.
[♪♪♪]
Why do you care so much?
I don't.
Because Fievel's going to die.
I'd rather die than listen.
Who's going to die?
Yeah.
Dean says the exterminator
is coming
because of our rat.
I'd like to exterminate
this conversation.
What are you doing?
He's sitting in Jeff's chair,
so he's trying
to act like Jeff.
ALL:
Oh! Oh.
Uh, e-mail.
I thought you might wanna help
me because we are friends.
Take it from a former prom king.
Real friends help me
with things, not vice versa.
I would face my fears
to help you.
Exactly.
Because you're my friend.
Am I?
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
♪ Beneath the pale moonlight ♪
Abed.
If he gets any nuttier,
they'll put him on The View.
[CHUCKLES]
That works. Yeah.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna study.
Ah!
Fievel?
Fievel.
[SQUEAKING]
[WHISPERS] Fievel.
Fievel.
Woo-woo-woo.
Okay, thank you.
Green Week was a rousing success
here at Greendale.
And now for our band,
Greene Daeye.
They're not
the real Green Day.
Thought we should just rip
that Band-Aid off quickly. Okay.
Hey. What's up?
Hey!
Just got your text, man.
Wanna hang out?
Because if you don't,
I will fail you.
Actually, I had an idea
for an extra-credit project.
We've been asked to dedicate
our first song
to "Señor and Señora Chang."
She said
she didn't wanna talk to me.
I didn't tell her
you wanted to talk.
"The estimation of market value
of brownies has...
I, uh-- Target group--"
Ms. Bennett,
I'm afraid I have to ask you
to put down the cards.
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
♪ Beneath the pale moonlight ♪
Uh... I-- Uh...
♪ Someone's thinking of me ♪
♪ And loving me tonight ♪
[SQUEAKING]
[BAND PLAYING
UPBEAT CELTIC MUSIC]
TROY:
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
♪ Someone's saying a prayer ♪
They are wonderful.
We all love brownies.
They're delicious.
If you love brownies,
you love life.
ABED:
♪ And even though I know ♪
♪ How very far apart we are ♪
Orgasmically delicious.
TROY:
♪ Wishing on
The same bright star ♪
♪ And when the night wind ♪
♪ Starts to sing
A lonesome lullaby ♪
TROY:
♪ It helps to think
We're sleeping ♪
♪ Underneath the same big sky ♪
[CHANG YELLS]
BOTH:
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
♪ If love can see us through ♪
Here's Brownie!
♪ Then we'll be together ♪
♪ Somewhere out there ♪
♪ Out where dreams ♪
♪ Come true ♪
[SQUEAKING]
God, he's on my leg!
He's on my leg! Aah!
[WHIMPERING]
Disgusting.
Thank you.
What's Chang doing?
He's getting a refill
on his void.
I got an A on my presentation
and a lot of the credit goes
to Pierce.
And I had a great sandwich.
We found the stupid rat.
Abed's gonna shut up about it.
It's true.
I have something to say.
I've been a horrible husband.
And I've been
a horrible teacher.
I'd like to thank my student,
Jeff Winger,
for showing me that
and helping me fix my marriage.
No more 20-page essays
due on Monday.
Oh, that's nice.
Thank you.
Although, Winger,
you should write
a one-page essay called:
"Taking Advantage
of the Emotionally Vulnerable."
Boo-yah.
You did that for us?
Mm. Kind of.
You know, I thought
hanging out with you guys
was the worst way
to pass Spanish.
I was wrong.
Well, we're the best.
Jeff, I'm sorry I called you
a handsome hobo.
If you need help
with that essay,
you can rejoin the group.
JEFF:
Thanks.
What are you guys
talking to me for?
You go dance.
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC]
I know your secret.
I know about the chair.
Whoa.
What model did you get?
It's the Tsunami 3000
Anniversary Edition. You?
The Devil's Drench XJ11.
This is gonna be awesome.
We should establish
base camps.
What part of library
do you want?
North east is closest
to drinking fountain, which--
All right, guys,
are we gonna do this thing?
Oh, ha-ha! Pierce,
I hope that's the tiny gun
that you throw at us
to confuse us
while you grab the giant gun
taped to your back.
Seriously, this hardly
seems like a fair fight. Aah!
Aah! Oh, it's pepper water!
Oh, it's pep--
Who puts pepper
in water?