[♪♪♪]
I booked a sketch artist,
an improv troupe,
and a laser projecting
a burning pelvis
onto the ceiling.
A laser?
This isn't
gonna be your mother's
sexually transmitted disease
awareness fair.
You've been quite the helper,
Annie.
Oh, STD fair, guys.
Catch knowledge.
Mm-mm.
You think you're better
than me?
No.
You stick to quoting movie
lines, I'll stick to sports.
Trying to reduce
my pop cultural referencing.
Well, you're not moving
into sports.
You and I are playing
real basketball, right now.
Sounds fun.
No, it doesn't.
And it won't be.
ANNIE: Catch knowledge.
Sorry, not interested
in ignoring your
very important cause.
Hi, I'm Jeff Winger.
Oh, Sabrina is my
new secretary.
Secretary is a little
degrading to women.
I help the dean
do office-y things.
Oh, gender saved.
My casual friend
and I
gonna have
a non-romantic breakfast
if you'd like to join us.
Cafeteria's closed.
Fortune cookie?
PELTON: Isn't it great?
Greendale is the latest campus
to catch a case of
public-health fever.
You know the toilets
in the women's bathrooms
don't have seats, right?
Because they keep
getting stolen.
Sabrina,
take a note.
I want hidden cameras
in every stall.
Problem solved.
"You will get AIDS."
Flip it over.
"Unless you go
to the STD fair."
I wrote that.
Congratu-- Horrible.
See you later.
Catch knowledge.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
Jeff,
you and I are friends, right?
Okay.
You may have noticed
a recent change in my demeanor.
I haven't.
I have a new girlfriend.
She is super-smart,
if you know what I mean.
I always know what you mean.
Can't wait for you to meet her.
You know, when you
catch a big fish,
you wanna stuff her
and put her on the mantle.
How about tonight?
I doubt it.
Troy and I played basketball.
Don't gloat.
It's impossible
to guard you.
Your eyes are too
gentle and mysterious.
Hey, guys, Jeff and I
are double-dating tonight
with my new girlfriend.
BOTH: Ooh!
You got that
from "I doubt it"?
Pierce has got
a girlfriend.
Great. What does she do?
She's an escort.
Oh.
Some mysteries
solve themselves.
No, that's just her profession.
She doesn't escort me.
No, no.
I met her in my marketing class.
And I'm taking Doreen
to Annie's mixer tonight.
You mean the STD fair.
Catch knowledge.
Taking a call girl
to an STD fair?
There's a joke here.
So, Jeff, dust off that
black book
and rustle up a honey.
Is there a pill that
makes the word "no" clearer?
It is short notice. Probably
couldn't get a date anyway.
BOTH:
Ooh.
I'm sure you're right.
BOTH:
Ooh.
Something to do with crabs.
They're food but also a disease?
Jeff,
for your feather flashing,
when was the last time
you scored?
I don't know the precise date,
Pierce, because I'm not you.
So there's no receipt.
Ooh.
Ehh.
Oh, come on.
You shouldn't take pot shots
at some woman
just because you can't
get a date.
I can get dates
any time I want.
What is this, some joke?
No, this is.
"Don't eat the crab dip."
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
Ahh! You hear that,
Annie?
That's the sound
of STDs screaming,
[HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
"No. Stop being
so aware of us."
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
And it's all thanks to you.
I was voted "most likely
to succeed" at my rehab clinic.
Well, in recognition
of all your hard work,
I have decided that
you should conduct
the condom demonstration.
You're gonna be center stage
showing everyone
how to put a condom
on a, uh--
Well, what my dad called
a Jimmy Carter.
Um, I don't know
if I'm the right person.
Don't worry.
Not a real one.
No, it's an anatomically
correct model, you know.
But trust me, eyes closed,
you can't tell the difference.
Mmm. Okay.
[WHIMPERS]
[♪♪♪]
[LINE RINGING]
Hey, it's Jeff Winger.
Well, I wanted to see
what you were doing tonight.
Do I know your name?
What kind of question is that?
Of course I know.
Well, if I answer now,
you'll never learn
a valuable lesson about trust,
Jennifer.
Crap. Ugh.
Pierce really
got to you, huh?
It has been a dry spell.
But it's been a while since
I've tried. So I'm trying.
Yeah, I can see that.
This is a lot of outgoing calls.
"Car Wash Redhead."
"Tube Top R.E.M. Concert."
"Juror Number 6."
That sounds aboveboard.
At least you have "Mommy."
That's not my mom.
Dude, not cool.
You saying "dude"
is not cool.
What are you doing?
[PHONE RINGS]
[BRITTA CHUCKLES]
"Hot Blonde Spanish Class"?
You're welcome.
This is the phone book
of a man in his 20s.
The women literally
have no identities.
It's pretty shallow.
You're right.
I can't believe I haven't
seen it before now.
Whatever. I'm gonna go
study with Shirley.
Well, I'll be here,
rethinking my way of life.
Mm.
[♪♪♪]
Call "Mommy."
Guys, I have a problem.
The dean wants me
to demonstrate
proper use of a condom
at the fair by putting
one on a mannequin's
stupid thing-a-mob.
It's a big honor
but I'm gonna screw it up.
Well,
it's easy enough to practice.
Do you have a banana?
This is an anatomically correct
model I'll be handling.
Real whatchamacallits
are nothing like bananas.
Are they?
Have you never seen one?
Shh!
Annie, being a virgin
in this day and age
is something to be proud of.
You're like a unicorn.
I'm not a unicorn.
I had relations
with my high school boyfriend.
We did it
to Madonna's Erotica
on the floor
of his walk-in closet.
But he wouldn't let me
look at it.
He cried after and during.
He's gay now.
[WHISPERS]
He was gay then.
So you never seen one
when you were growing up?
Like, on the Internet, in a
picture, or Harvey Keitel's?
Caught glimpses, but I've never
got a real good look at one.
What I need to do is practice
on the actual model.
But the dean has
it locked in his office.
Okay, that's easy. We'll go
to him, ask him if we--
No. I--
This is really embarrassing.
I don't want anyone to know.
I wanna figure out how to do it
and get it over with.
The dean is counting on me,
and I want him to know
that I'm someone he can trust.
We have to break
into his office.
I have no problem
with that.
BRITTA:
I think I could do that.
[CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Oh, hello, Jeffrey.
Hi, Pierce.
I was just going
into the fair
to wait for my
smoking-hot date.
That's nice.
How about you?
Uh, were you ever able to,
you know, come up with a date?
No, no,
because I didn't try,
because taking a date
to an STD fair would be lame.
Don't worry about it,
kid.
What you're going through
is a dry spell.
From my experience,
they don't last any more
than 12, 13 years.
Excuse me.
No gonorrhea,
please, please, please.
No gonorrhea.
Ow! It burns.
That's gonna hurt.
Gross. Dean,
your assistant,
is she single?
What are her likes
and dislikes?
Yes, on single.
She likes hip-hop and horses.
Dislikes beards--
I was done talking.
Is it me or are horses
the most beautiful creatures?
They're so majestic.
Totally.
This morning when I was shaving
and listening to the new Jay-Z,
Was thinking how I wanna squeeze
in a quick gallop this weekend.
Do you own a horse?
Can you ever really
own a horse?
JEFF: Pierce.
Yeah?
This is Sabrina.
Thirty seconds
after you walked away,
I asked her to be my date
and she said yes.
You must have a great
personality.
Thank you.
Jeff, you proved me wrong.
You got a girl.
Yeah, I did.
Oh.
This is Doreen.
Ready for our double-date?
Yes, I am.
Wait, how'd you do that?
[♪♪♪]
Is this the best safe-sex
fair or what?
Check out these condoms.
All along the side
it says, "Greendale!"
Exclamation point,
my idea.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Wow. Me,
in a dune buggy,
with syphilis.
This is going on the fridge.
Heh, heh. Look how gorgeous
Doreen is tonight.
Hey, can we--?
Let's lay out our plans
for the evening.
You wingman me,
I wingman you.
Maybe we split up
for a little hoo-ha
and then meet in the morning
for eggs and details.
That sounds like the worst
combination plate ever.
Thanks.
Argh!
I can't believe
you beat me again.
Do you want
my stuffed animal?
We're arm wrestling.
[GRUNTS]
Like Stallone in Over the Top.
Don't I need a truck and a son?
The rules are, "You suck."
Let's go.
I wanna wait for a more
inspiring song.
This score isn't right.
There we go.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
[YELLING]
Oh, my God.
You broke my hand,
you bastard.
[♪♪♪]
I can't do anything
with this.
No, let me see that.
Oh, I can see
through the door.
[BRITTA AND ANNIE GASP]
SHIRLEY:
Oh, yeah, thar she blows.
I wanna see, I wanna see.
Okay, go, go, go.
Go ahead.
[BRITTA AND SHIRLEY GIGGLING]
I'm the one that needs to see.
Okay, okay, okay.
It's okay.
Oh, boy.
Oh, I had it wrong.
Is that considered large?
Oh, no.
Yes.
What in the reverse Porky's
is going on here?
You know, Doreen
speaks six languages.
You should hear her
order wine in French.
Hey, honey, say,
"Cabernet sauvigonenon."
You're embarrassing me.
You know a lot
about wine?
Well, I did have a client
who owned a vineyard in Napa.
He was into S&amp;M and merlot
so we called it S&amp;M&amp;M.
Honey, you're boring
the crap out of Jeff.
Be right back.
I have to make tinkles.
Well, then, I'm gonna go
get us another round.
You know,
you are not what I expected.
You're smart, you're classy,
you're not wearing go-go boots.
They're in the shop.
You know,
despite what people think,
I actually spend
most of my time talking.
As men get older, they wanna
spend time with someone
they can have a real
conversation with.
That is going to suck.
"Going to," Jeff?
Come on, Sabrina's cute,
but she thinks that
Monty Python
is the evil snake
from Harry Potter.
Trust me,
I know girls I can converse with
who are way more annoying.
I will take "tinkles"
over
"we need to talk" every time.
Hey, babe.
Ready to show me
that Lexus?
I thought you'd never ask.
Doreen,
it was very nice
to meet you.
You can do better.
Here.
Oh, they already left?
What a couple of nincompoops.
Uh, before I buy dinner,
I have to ask.
Is there any lovemaking
on the table?
We're through, Pierce.
I'm gonna go to the bar
and you can join me
if you'd like.
And we can still have
a lovely evening,
but it will cost you
200 bucks.
That is a pretty
big discount.
♪ In the middle
Of the darkest night ♪
♪ I see a light shining ♪
♪ Right into your eyes ♪
♪ I lose control
Again and again ♪
I had no idea alcohol
would make people horny.
It makes me sleepy.
I don't--
Dean?
Yeah.
We have a 597 currently
going on in your office.
597? There's a dog-fighting
ring in my office?
No.
I'm gonna turn him around
and we're gonna cover him up.
Okay, ladies,
I am shocked
at the reverse Porky's
that has happened here.
BRITTA:
I don't see
what the big deal is.
Annie needed to look
at the model of the pen--
Okay, the P-word
has entered into play.
That's exactly
why I wanted Gayle,
our school counselor here,
and Monique, who's keeping
record, to ensure
we discuss
these sensitive topics
in a legally appropriate
manner.
I think everyone
should say "penis"
so we can take away
the negative power of the word.
Yeah? So everybody.
ALL: Penis.
She didn't say it.
Now, why did you break
in to see the penis?
Wow, I really do feel more
comfortable saying that now.
I just wanna focus on the girl
who won't say "penis."
[♪♪♪]
This is a judgment-free zone,
so express yourself.
You know what?
I don't want
to express myself.
I don't wanna sit
in a room full of people
and say...
the P-word.
I like being repressed.
I am totally comfortable
being uncomfortable
with my sexuality.
And maybe, just maybe,
if everyone were
a little more like me,
we wouldn't have
to have an STD fair.
BRITTA: You go, girl.
That's my pumpkin.
Mm-hm.
By the way, now that I've
gotten a good look at one,
I don't see what all the fuss
was about.
A giant thumb in a turtleneck.
Whoop-dee-doo!
[DOOR OPENS
THEN CLOSES]
[♪♪♪]
[SABRINA GASPS AND MOANS]
[PHONE VIBRATES]
You have a really
awesome body.
You probably hear that
all the time.
Not as much
as I should.
[SABRINA MOANS]
Professor.
What?
I'm not a professor.
But you're at Greendale
and you're old.
I'm a student.
Yikers.
Yeah. It's pretty much
yikers for me too.
Well, I guess I can make
an exception, professor.
[MOANS]
You know,
I can't do this.
What?
But this is your car.
Keep it.
But--
[♪♪♪]
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes! How do you like
those apples?
I don't like those apples.
I'm so upset.
It was just a fluke
I won those other games.
Troy.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Wow, this may be
the only STD fair
to actually spread STDs.
Shut up, Ben.
MAN:
ACondom water balloon fight!
[ALL LAUGHING]
What the hell?
Dude,
these are leaking.
[LAUGHING]
CHANG:
Oh, my God.
That's why you don't
print things on condoms.
Everyone's getting preggers
and it's all your fault.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, man.
Troy,
all the condoms are faulty.
As the best athlete on campus,
I need you to run to my office
and make an announcement
before everyone leaves.
Dean, I am not the best
athlete on campus.
Abed is.
I know you let me win
the race.
You didn't say anything.
That's because...
I wanted it to be true.
You're a really good friend.
No, Abed.
You are.
For the love of God, run!
Okay.
TROY:
Go, Abed, go.
Before people
sex one another.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
There he is.
Back already.
Detail time?
I stopped.
I don't know what's wrong
with me. I mean, she's hot.
I think this place
is sapping my life force.
Oh, it's not Greendale,
Jeff, it's you.
You're becoming more mature.
A man reaches a point
in his life
where he stops looking for
a place to hang his underwear
and starts looking
for a place to hang his hat.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was waiting for that to become
inappropriate or racist.
What happened
to Doreen?
Oh, uh,
she said if I wanted to
continue, I'd have to pay.
Oh, man,
that is rough.
No, it was
a wake-up call.
Doreen is a special lady.
I did not treat her right.
I have stuff to work on,
you know?
You'll get there.
We're both gonna get there.
Here's to being better men.
Cheers.
So can I borrow 200 bucks?
Tell Doreen I say hi.
You know, for 220,
I can get--
I'll give you 250
if you don't finish telling me.
Now I can get it twice.
Ah, college.
Best years of our lives.
[THE FRATELLIS'
"WHISTLE FOR THE CHOIR" PLAYING]
Oop.
♪ So if you're lonely ♪
♪ Why'd you say
You're not lonely ♪
♪ Oh, you're a silly girl ♪
♪ I know I hurt you so ♪
♪ It's just like you
To come and go ♪
♪ And know me... ♪
ABED [OVER PA]:
Attention, Greendale students.
Don't use the condoms.
If you're going to have sex
tonight, don't use condoms.
[ABED PANTING]
♪ A girl like
You's just irresistible ♪
"The characteristic of an acid
to donate or accept a proton
"cannot be quantified
for individual species.
"Comparing two
donor-acceptor systems,
the proton transposition
HA plus H2O..."
Abed?
Yeah, Troy?
Can you get me a glass
of water?
Mm, Sure.
Thank you, Abed.