[LAUGHING]
Welcome back!
Hi! Hello!
Hi.
What did you do over break?
TROY:
Oh, it's so awesome.
Me and Abed played
this video game.
It is so dope.
It's a whole city.
Drive anywhere.
Rent an apartment.
You could do taxes.
Don't get audited.
You could even enroll
in community college.
Right now, it sounds
as boring as real life,
but it is not.
Vacations are wasted
on the young.
You guys gotta get out there
and see the world at some point
or you're gonna miss
your entire lives.
Where did you go, Britta?
Amsterdam, I think.
I'll know more
when I find my camera.
Guess what happened to me.
Oh, Pierce,
you became a grandfather?
No, I became even cooler.
These ironic T-shirts
are all the rage.
Let's get one thing straight.
I wish I was still a lawyer,
I'm only here
because I'm hot for Britta,
and I don't want
to be anybody's friend.
Just kidding.
Bring it in here,
you knuckleheads.
[ALL LAUGHING AND CHATTERING]
You know, I gotta say,
I-- I took a look back
at the guy I was last semester,
and I realized,
that guy was a drag.
ALL: No.
Good to hear you admit it.
No, the truth is,
this is a new semester,
a new Jeff.
Greendale is where I am
and I am gonna make
the best of it.
Oh, that's nice.
You're like Hawkeye on M*A*S*H.
He kept his upbeat humor
and charm,
even in the 11th year
of the Korean War.
Yeah. Well, don't go
changing too much, Jeff.
I think we all like you
just the way you were.
Well, I appreciate that,
but--
Did you just teleport here?
No, I snuck in
during the group hug.
You guys don't remember me?
Buddy, from Spanish class.
Yeah,
it's Buddy from Spanish class.
I've never seen you
before in my life.
[ALL CHATTERING]
ABED:
I've seen Buddy before.
Sits in the corner,
next to the dead plant.
Thank you, Abed.
Sometimes, I have a tendency
to melt into the background.
It's just my body type,
but I definitely know you guys.
From watching you
all last semester grow together.
[♪♪♪]
F. F minus.
Did you say S?
He said F.
CHANG: Who cheated?
I did it.
[CLASS CHATTERING]
Britta cheated?
But why?
Give me back my bra, Annie.
[SCOFFS]
I'm not even wearing a bra.
[BOTH SCREAMING]
I don't even care who wins.
What?
I sleep a lot in class, that one
might have been a dream.
Well, Buddy, as you know, we
haven't had Spanish class yet,
so this meeting was more
just for catching up
between friends.
I heard that. Let's do it.
Well, maybe--
So I--
Heh. Sorry, Britta.
I'll go first. Uh--
I'm sure you guys have
a natural rapport and timing,
and you know you're scared
that adding a new member
might throw everything off
of its natural--
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ I can't count
The reasons I should stay ♪
Rhythm, but I feel like
I know you guys already.
So you know, let me in,
just tell me the rules,
and I will follow.
Well, you already broke
the only rule I have.
The rule about worrying
about rules.
That's what I'm saying too.
Yeah!
♪ Spanish studying is better ♪
♪ When you're Buddy-ing
Around ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
Hey, Jeff.
Hey.
Excuse me. Um--
I received a text message
about free Sephora samples?
Ha-ha. It was me.
Sorry about the ruse,
but I have something better
than exfoliating soap
to rub on you.
An opportunity. Mm.
As you can see,
I am resurrecting
the Greendale Gazette
Journal Mirror.
And we need a student editor.
Someone
with a real world savvy
that extends beyond
how to huff the ink.
Actually, Dean,
I'm resolved to spend
this semester being more--
This would be your office.
Relaxed and awesome.
This is the first desk
I've seen in six months
that doesn't have
"Zeppelin Rules" carved in it.
And you get
an English credit.
Well, that ain't bad neither.
I'm in.
Yeah.
Guys, meet your new editor!
Mr. Winger is very excited
to help you
bring a voice back
to the campus.
Jeff, I need
to take your picture.
Good, we got it.
Okay.
You guys
knock yourselves out.
Welcome aboard, Jeff.
This is my article
on the school's
new water heater.
You've got chops, kid.
But we need your talent
on a bigger story.
Pizza wars. Who's got the best
slice in town?
Start with Big Nick's.
Bring us a large with sausage.
You. I heard a rumor
that Riley's Liquor
is selling
to underage students.
So I need an undercover exposé.
Find out how much
they'll sell you
of anything cold and imported.
You expect me to watch you
do that without telling on you?
That's a hard-hitting question,
Annie.
Are you a reporter?
No. They've got me editing
the crossword
because I'm a girl.
And because I love crosswords.
Well, now you love the streets.
You're my ace newshound.
Ace? You can do that?
We can do anything we want.
It's Greendale.
Now, go find me that story.
ABED:
This character reboot
is really gelling for you, Jeff.
That was all classic Hawkeye.
Sending soldiers out
for liquor.
Slyly sidestepping
the problematic scrutiny
of Annie "Hot Lips" Edison.
Mm?
I should build you a still
for making Hawkeye martinis.
Of all your pop cultural
fixations,
this is one I can
work with, Abed.
Call me Radar?
When you've earned it.
Now, I know the news
of Señor Chang's death
over winter break
was a shock to us all.
But we should take comfort
in the fact
that he did not suffer
when his moped hit
the side of that Arby's.
So sad.
But best semester ever.
[LAUGHS]
[ALL GASP]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Beat it. All right.
That was a professional actress.
I am a man who can never die,
and this has been
your first taste
of Spanish 1-0- dos,
the semester
I get inside your cabezas.
[CHOMPS NOISILY]
[BELCHES]
♪ I am Señor Chang ♪
♪ And I'm so ill ♪
♪ This is a warning
I can't be killed ♪
♪ All in your cabeza
Without a chaser ♪
♪ Not another teacher ♪
♪ With this much flavor
Chang ♪
Saw that coming.
Hey, guys.
See you in study group.
Hoo-aah!
Ah!
Uh, Jeff,
can he really just decide
he's one of us?
PIERCE:
He throws off our balance.
We've got three chicks,
three dudes,
and now two weirdoes.
Sorry, Abed.
Not all weirdoes are bad.
Buddy might be a puckish
agent of change
that changes our lives for the
better through musical montage.
Or he could have a row
of jars
waiting for our genitals.
Yo, I need my genitals.
You know
who you guys sound like?
Me, from last semester.
Cynical. Elitist.
Oh.
Rakishly good-looking.
Thank you.
Well, we should at least
get together to talk
about membership policies,
right?
Hey, don't ask me.
Dealing with problems
ain't my job no more.
My new job is hanging out,
having fun and cracking wise.
Oh, must be nice.
Suppose, I decide that's my job?
[ALL LAUGHING]
Jeff.
I hope you've got
an army of raisins,
because I've got
a major scoop.
In October, there was a free
Toni Braxton concert
on the quad--
You don't need to remind me.
When a last-minute mix-up
shifted the showtime by an hour,
an anonymous text message
went out alerting students
of the change.
Okay.
Not okay.
Because the text message
was sent exclusively
to black students.
And one French kid named Lebron.
That's profiling.
This is front page juice.
I gotta find out
who sent the text.
Have you called
the number that sent it?
Well, nobody's that stupid,
right?
[GROWLS]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Um--
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Wrong number.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
No, no. That was a good cover.
So whoever it is
keeps hanging up,
but he can't hide forever.
Annie the reporter.
Good times.
Listen up, I just want to say,
thank you guys real much--
Real much? Duh.
Thank you guys
very much for this.
It's a dream come true.
Aww.
Oh.
Now, let's study some Spanish.
So for the essay,
we conjugate--
Conjugate?
Conjugal. Visit.
Lame. Okay, stick and move,
stick and move.
Okay,
so for the essay portion--
♪ Annie got an essay portion ♪
♪ Annie gonna move ♪
♪ Her luscious fanny
All day long ♪
Hey, Buddy can sing,
you guys.
Well, that's great.
Annie's pretty young,
we try not to sexualize her.
I'm sorry. Whoa!
Okay, look, I did--
You know what?
It's your study group,
and I don't know
if you perceive it
as something
that could be improved
but I do have some ideas.
Here's one right here. Boom.
I was thinking, as a group,
we could start saying,
"You go, girl."
Not in a way that's, you know,
oh, I'm so cool saying,
"You go, girl."
But in a way that
we're kind of winking at it.
Bottom line,
you guys need a chubby,
agile guy.
Did anyone see
Paul Blart: Marl Car--
Paul Blart: Mall Cop.
I'm like that, okay?
I'm fat
and I'm physical, okay?
And I'm strong, hmm,
and I can kick.
Ow!
[ALL GASP]
Dude, sorry.
Jeff, Jeff?
JEFF: No, no, it's fine.
Just a little nosebleed,
I get them when it's dry,
or when my face gets kicked.
I'll get some paper towels.
Goodness.
[♪♪♪]
Did someone say something
about a meeting
to discuss member policy?
[♪♪♪]
Well, I think,
it's obvious to everyone,
that this Buddy fellow
has a few Fruit Loops loose
so I think,
no matter what we do,
we gotta do it
with grace and caution.
I say, we keep Buddy
in the group.
What?
PIERCE:
I've given it a lot of thought
and, frankly, I like his
in-your-face style.
TROY:
I can't stop thinking
about his high kick.
His ratio of girth
to hip flexibility
is mesmerizing.
I like his idea of ironically
saying, "You go, girl."
You go, girl.
Wait, so you kick high enough
and you get in the group?
If we're gonna add people,
I think we should
consider my friend Gary.
I'm sorry, Shirley,
you friend Gary
is so boring.
He was raised in Finland,
he doesn't get our humor.
So if we're gonna add a chair
for every bong-ripping,
good-time charlie,
with a song in his heart,
I move we institute hazing.
Well, in The Right Stuff,
the novel by Tom Wolfe--
PIERCE:
This is why we need new blood.
I'm so bored
of your pop culture references,
and your cigarette-legged jeans.
Gary wears loose-fitting jeans.
Gary is off the table.
He is a buzzkill.
He grew up in a land
without sun.
[ALL SHOUTING]
Take a vote.
They'd probably vote him in.
They won't.
Guys. Guys,
let's take a vote.
Secret vote,
everybody cover your eyes.
We won't know the result.
Say your vote out loud.
We'll know
each other's voices.
Troy's got a point.
Holy crap. Wow.
It says here,
some guy in Seattle
went nuts and killed
his entire driver's ed class
with a meat tenderizer.
SHIRLEY: Oh, no.
We have to be careful.
[♪♪♪]
Okay.
On the count of three,
everybody who wants
to keep Buddy out,
raise your hand.
You lied about the guy
in Seattle
with the meat tenderizer.
You put your thumb
on the scale.
You did it with a smile
and you did it
so you could keep smiling.
You're Hawkeye.
And with Buddy gone,
staying that way
will be a lot easier.
PELTON:
I am not racist.
I had 20 minutes
to let people know
Toni Braxton was starting early
and 273 text messages left
before my rate tripled.
Racial profiling
may not be right,
but it can be economical.
Tell me, dean,
when I refer to you
in my article, would you prefer
imbecile or incompetent?
I'd prefer incompetent,
but what I really want--
It doesn't matter
what you want.
The people want the truth,
I have to give it to them,
and I won't let anyone
stand in my way.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Jeffrey.
I'm the least racist person
in the world.
My best friend,
when I was 6 years old,
was a black man.
Okay, look.
I've learned my lesson.
I've got unlimited texting now.
But if she runs that story,
I will lose this job,
and this job is my life.
She listens to you.
Well, next time
we're both hanging out,
having fun,
I could try cracking wise
about it with her.
You do what you think
is right.
[HUMMING THEME FROM M*A*S*H]
That's enough.
Okay.
I'm just saying,
it's not exactly Watergate.
I mean, you like the dean,
he's trying
to help you transfer.
Yeah, and this time,
he might succeed.
If this article breaks out,
I can apply
for journalism scholarships.
Nobody will care
about my time in rehab
if they think I'm a writer.
Annie, as your upbeat friend,
I gotta say, let this go.
This is Greendale, Jeff,
we can do whatever we want.
BUDDY:
♪ I'm sorry, I'm sorry
I'm so damn sorry ♪
♪ I'm sorry, I'm sorry ♪
♪ Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry ♪
♪ I'm so, I'm sorry
I'm so so sorry ♪
Didn't anyone tell Buddy
he was out?
I guess
we thought you would.
My lord, my lady,
you missed my apology song.
Yeah, I'll--
I'll tell them about it later.
Jeff, I am so sorry
about the other day.
Buddy,
yesterday,
the group took a vote.
[GROANS]
And you seem to have
figured out the rest of it.
[SOBBING]
Was it the high kick?
Was it, "You go, girl?"
Oh, you guys think
you're so cool.
No, we don't think
we're cool at all.
Just a bit.
I put myself out there
for you!
I laid my soul bare.
I made you guys lemon squares
with free-range eggs
that I baked with my own hands.
Maybe a little less sugar
next time.
Well, I'm not leaving.
Oh, come on.
Be relaxed, like me.
Leave.
You're not relaxed.
You're an uptight
puppet master.
And these
are your little puppets.
[ALL SHOUTING]
[SHOUTING STOPS]
Buddy,
just be reasonable and go.
Make me, Hitler.
[GASPS]
Okay, so, uh,
since Buddy's not leaving,
he'll just be the person
who we wish wasn't here
while we study.
Try getting that deal
from Hitler.
Shall we?
I'm studying with you.
No, you're not.
Everyone stop studying.
Okay.
You're not in the group.
Okay, then go study
somewhere else.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
No, no, no.
Oh, no.
No! I wanna study
with you guys. No!
No!
[GRUNTING]
[CRYING]
No!
I hate you!
I hate your study group!
I hate it!
You suck!
I hate you!
[BUDDY CRYING AND SHOUTING]
And you are not running
that story.
Why not?
Because I said so.
Does anybody have a problem
with how that was handled?
[ALL MURMURING]
Exactly the way
I would've done it.
BUDDY [CRYING]:
You suck!
Who are you kidding, Abed?
I just dragged
a screaming, crying man
out of a library
with his pants down.
No. Martinis
are for Hawkeyes.
I'm the same uptight jerk
I was last semester.
Jeff, what's your favorite
episode of M*A*S*H?
The one with, uh, the Army.
That's what I thought.
If you had actually
seen the show you'd know
that Hawkeye didn't just
bed nurses and drink martinis.
He also had blood sprayed
on his face
and barked orders
when the choppers came in.
If he didn't, people died.
He was a leader, Jeff.
That's your job.
Yeah? What's in it for me?
Hey.
Annie.
I-- I'm sorry that I yelled.
I'm glad you did.
It didn't even really occur
to me what I was doing
until I saw
how upset you were.
I never want to be the reason
you're mad,
because you're Jeff Winger.
So thanks
for getting mad.
It was nothing.
I guess that's the upside,
isn't it?
Thank you, Radar.
Ooh. You made me so happy
I just peed a little.
I don't think violence
is the answer
when we make decisions.
[ALL GASP]
Hi, guys.
Hi, Buddy.
Can you, um--?
Excuse us?
For one crazy stalker?
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Listen up,
we outnumber this guy,
six to one.
Annie, you flash your breasts
as a decoy for the bum-rush.
Pierce?
Britta, don't be upset.
I didn't pick you as a decoy
because your breasts
are so old.
Why is he even here? Hello.
JEFF:
I invited him.
Buddy's crime
is thinking we're cool.
But I get it.
If I were him,
and I missed out on you guys,
I'd be sitting
in that classroom,
watching, wondering.
So how can I exclude someone
from something
that I'm so lucky to have.
Oh.
I say we let him in.
[CHUCKLING]
JEFF:
Hey, Buddy.
Welcome to the group.
Oh, yes!
You will not regret this.
[CHATTERING AND CHUCKLING]
There he is.
Hey, Buddy.
Hmm?
the group thought
about what you said.
We took a vote.
And you're in.
Oh! No way.
I'm in the cool group?
It's like Christmas morning
for the guy.
MAN:
Welcome.
This is--
Oh, this is awkward.
You guys were my safety. Pfft.
Hey, hey, Buddy, you don't have
to worry about them.
You're with us now.
Come on.
Ha-ha! Boo!
Go!
I love the kick!
It's amazing.
The kicks are the best.
[GROUP CHATTERING]
And that, ladies and gentlemen,
is why I voted to keep him.
It would have been nice
to have another person
in the group.
I'll call Gary.
[THEME FROM M*A*S*H PLAYING]
So it says here
you want to join as a twosome?
I don't see
that as a selling point.
We work really well together.
Let me hear that rap thing
of yours again.
[BOTH RAPPING IN SPANISH]
I'm gonna talk it over
with the others.
Cool.
Thanks for your time.
You traitors! I am appalled
at your lack of loyalty.
Yeah, you better run.
[WHISPERS] Have you decided?
We saw your tape.
We're passing.
I don't pop on video.
Let me do the song in person.
♪ Getting rid of Britta ♪
♪ Getting rid of the B ♪
♪ She's a GDB ♪
♪ She's a no-good B ♪