BRITTA:
Missed you at lunch today.
Did you slip out for a quickie
with Professor Hot Stuff?
Her name's Michelle
and how did you know?
There's a gold star
on your fly.
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
You weren't kidding.
It's nice to have a girlfriend
with a sense of humor
and one who recognizes
good work.
[MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
See, that's G.
That's the most important chord.
In my mind, it--
It stands for God.
Why is Annie talking
to Micro-Nipples?
Vaughn? Whatever.
But not like a Bible God 'cause
I think god is everything.
You're complicated.
♪ Annie ♪
♪ Annie
Where you going today? ♪
Spanish class.
♪ Spanish ♪
You know what I don't get?
He never wears a shirt.
He never wears shoes.
Why hasn't he died
from lack of service?
[♪♪♪]
Watching another movie
in your dorm?
Kickpuncher starring
Don "The Demon" Donaldson
as a cyborg cop whose punches
have the power of kicks.
That sounds awful.
I'll bring the popcorn.
BOTH:
Cool.
Uh, you watch bad movies
on purpose?
Yeah, we make fun of them.
Hmm.
Don't embarrass yourself.
I'm sure they don't want
to invite the housewife.
If she doesn't mind
reinforcing the stereotype,
I bet she'd have fun.
Care to join us?
Usually when a movie's bad,
I stop watching.
But this sounds college-y.
What time
do you want us there?
Pierce, you don't wanna watch
a cyborg movie in Abed's dorm.
You wanna lay in your twin bed,
think about what you used to be.
What?
You think I'm too old
to make monkeyshines?
Come on, I'm younger
than three of you put together.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, Britta.
JEFF:
Everyone talks
about his nipples,
but his feet freak me out.
Britta!
Hey.
Can I ask you something?
About Vaughn?
Oh, yes,
I still don't know if that's
his first or last name.
He's sweet, actually.
I mean,
you must have thought so.
He has a sincerity
I found attractive
in a simpler time.
[SIGHS]
Would you...?
Um, I haven't...
And we haven't--
Anything.
I mean--
Wow, you and Vaughn?
Would it bug you?
Well, what about you and Troy?
Troy?
The other day I thought
he was trying to hold my hand.
But he had just mistaken me
for Abed.
He'll never think of me
that way.
Well, Annie,
I would have to be a villain
to tell you who to date.
Which I am not.
Britta, thank you.
You're the coolest girl
I've ever met.
Damn right,
give me some fivesies.
Whoo!
Turning it into a snake.
Oh, cool.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ I can't count
The reasons I should stay ♪
Hey, how's it going?
Did you hear? It's cute.
Annie and Vaughn.
Get to the cute part.
She's into him.
She asked for my blessing.
And you gave it?
Yeah, I'm done with him.
Look, this isn't about you,
you groovy hipster.
It's about Annie.
We're like
her Greendale parents.
You gotta say no to that stuff.
He's not that bad.
Yeah, not if you're 28 and
you're fooling around with him.
She's 18.
Her taste in men
is still being established.
Creepier and creepier dudes
will start thinking of her
as an option.
And it all starts with Vaughn.
He's a gateway douche bag.
People collide, things happen.
It can't be controlled, right?
That can be your toast at her
shotgun wedding to Star-Burns.
Oh, yeah, turn to your left.
Oh, now turn to your right.
Yes, we can see both of them.
Like a constellation
on your face.
How stupid. Hey.
Oh, what's up, dude? Yeah.
That guy over there?
He's a douche bag.
Hey, guys.
Hola!
I invited Señor Chang.
We're Netflix friends.
That's cool you're hanging out,
drinking beers with students.
Yeah, clearly none of my plans
fell through.
Let's get to the movie.
Wait. Oh, I'm sorry, Shirley.
I'll wait
if you wanna serve beverages.
You're gonna be waiting
a long-ass time.
[MUSIC PLAYS ON TV]
Oh, FBI warning,
I'm so scared.
Hey, that's not fair.
I didn't know we started.
NARRATOR [ON TV]:
It is the year 2006 A.D.
And nuclear war
has ravaged the planet.
I must have missed that.
Nice.
Between cities
is a free-fire zone,
ruled by scavengers,
drug dealers and terrorists.
Sounds like a Thanksgiving
at my house.
[ALL LAUGH]
They just come to me.
You want to buy some megadope?
It gets you mega high.
Will it get me
through this movie?
[ALL LAUGHING]
Freeze, police!
Freeze police?
Don't do that, they'll get cold.
[LAUGHS]
[GRUNTING OVER TV]
WOMAN:
You've done so much
for our city.
Kickpuncher, is there anything
that we can give you?
Yeah, two hours of my life back.
[ALL LAUGH]
Don't call me Kickpuncher.
Call me David.
PIERCE:
"Directed by Kim Yang."
Asian, can't direct,
can't drive.
[LAUGHS]
Dude, I'm right here.
Right there.
So clearly we're all a bunch
of funny people.
When are we doing this again?
Well, actually, tomorrow we--
No.
We were all gonna get--
I wouldn't.
Right?
Tomorrow night,
we're all gonna get together
and watch Kickpuncher 2:
Codename Punchkicker.
Well, I was just
warming up tonight.
Tomorrow you better
foam the runways
because I'm bringing
my A game.
Awesome.
All right, so check it.
It's like surfing without water.
All right, your turn.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
VAUGHN:♪ Annie's gonna ride ♪
Oh, my God.
♪ Annie's gonna ride the wave ♪
He's got her in some
kind of hippie collar.
I can hear her armpit hair
growing from here.
We've got to do something.
Okay, even if I agreed with you,
what are we gonna do?
Let's just center ourselves.
If we say we disapprove,
we'll drive her further
into his hemp-braceleted arms.
We need to be smart,
need to hatch a scheme.
Hatching schemes
is not really my wheelhouse.
Let's not confine ourselves
to your wheelhouse.
This problem won't respond
to tap dancing
or casual revelations
that you spent time in New York.
You're gonna get Upper Eastside,
I think we're done.
Hey, Winger, check out Annie.
Somebody just went to the top
of my to-do list.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, we need to hatch a scheme.
Thank you.
JEFF:
It's all very simple.
In Annie's world,
long before Vaughn,
she only had eyes for Troy.
So if Troy
becomes a real option,
Annie will drop Vaughn
in a hippie's heartbeat.
Crash course in manipulation.
You don't tell the person
what you want them to do.
You help them realize
they want to do it
so it can't be traced
back to you.
Hmm. Got it.
Chemistry, sexy.
You know what else is sexy?
Annie.
I know chemistry is sexy.
But Annie? I don't see it.
Well, every other guy
on campus does.
You really don't see
how pretty Annie is?
Maybe it's because I knew her
back in high school.
Before she dropped out,
she had braces, and acne,
and a pill addiction.
A nervous breakdown
ending with her running
through a plate glass door
screaming, "Everyone's a robot."
I see what's happening here.
Troy, I want you
to clear your head.
Done.
I'm gonna describe to you
a complete stranger
who happens happens to be
in our study group.
Would you excuse us
for a moment?
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
Annie? No kidding?
Come on,
you gotta be exaggerating.
Oh, man.
[CLEARS THROAT]
And she's Jewish?
I can't believe
I didn't see that.
Well, I guess she deserves
another shot.
Oh, wait. Never mind.
It's too late.
She's hooking up
with Vaughn.
Only to make you jealous.
BOTH: What?
She's helplessly
in love with you.
She's only with him
to get your attention.
And you have to give it
to her now.
Right, Jeff?
Sure.
But the point is,
we're not telling you
what to do.
Oh, yeah,
you didn't hear it from us.
[♪♪♪]
[WHISPERS]
Boo-ya.
I have the weirdest boner.
MAN [ON TV]:
I saw you die.
How can you be alive?
I guess it's just a bad day
for drug-dealing terrorists.
And a good day for...
Kickpuncher!
All right, guys,
you hear that pause
after he says, "And a good day"?
What do you got for me there?
A good day
for a nutritious breakfast.
I don't get it.
It's a good day
for a terrible movie.
A good day for hair products?
Oh, Buzz.
How many times you keep going
to go to that well?
Come on. I'm starting to wonder
if you deserve to be called
a community college
sketch comedy troupe.
I told you, on movie night
I need to blow these punks
out of the water.
I need
Phyllis Diller-grade stuff.
Wouldn't you rather
watch a movie with your friends
and have a good time?
What are you,
my third wife's therapist?
What if he said,
"It's a good day for,"
And you said,
"For being gay?"
[LAUGHS]
You are a genius.
He likes gay jokes.
What?
I said we write great jokes.
Don't flatter yourselves.
[♪♪♪]
Whoa.
Hey, Annie.
It's me, Troy.
Oh, I don't know where Abed is.
I can call him if you want.
No, I'm not looking
for my other half.
I'm looking for you, girl.
Oh.
Yeah.
Let that sink in
for a second.
Mm?
You know, I never noticed
how beautiful you are.
Troy, you're being weird.
Sorry it took me so long.
They made me find a shirt.
Vaughn,
you remember Troy.
We went to high school together
and he's in my study group.
Hey, what's up, man?
Hi, bro.
[CHUCKLES]
I'm not your bro, bro.
Oh, well, actually,
everyone is my bro
in the whole entire universe
because everything is connected.
Rocks, eagles, hats.
Yeah, some things are more
connected than others.
Like tarantulas
and me peeing my pants.
Or me and Annie.
What, wait.
Troy? What?
Tell him.
You've been in love with me
since high school.
What?
Is that true, Mountain Flower?
No!
I mean,
I never wanna lie to you.
So I will tell you,
I did have feelings for him.
But it's over, I swear.
You swear?
Like Britta swore
that she didn't like Jeff.
Then gave him
a copy of my poem
so he could laugh at me
with that Sherri Shepherd lady?
It's happening again.
Your study group is evil.
And you don't deserve ice cream.
[GASPS]
[♪♪♪]
Well, he's a baby.
Now, where were we?
I like him.
Why would you do that?
Come on, everybody knows
you want a cut of T-bone steak.
Jeff and Britta told me
how you feel.
Wait.
Jeff and Britta did what now?
Oh, you're even hotter
when you're angry.
Let's do this.
Red Shoe Diaries.
I think you know
I have a thing for butt stuff.
To Annie's inevitable breakup
with Grodie J. McConaughey.
And to her and Troy.
We did the right thing.
They belong together.
Plus, their babies
will be so cute.
Why would you say that?
Come on, you know
that babies are extra cute
when the parents are...
Both cute?
Do you want kids?
We'll see.
Put on something nice
and find me after lunch.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, guys.
Thanks for getting involved
in my love life.
That was super cool
and mature!
Since you're both idiots,
I should let you know
I'm being sarcastic.
Hey, guys. Thanks for
taking ugly Annie
out of the palm of my hand,
and turning her
into yet another hottie
that will never get with me!
Hey, guys, thanks for eating
all the macaroni.
Shut up, Leonard, nobody knows
what you're talking about.
I did eat all the macaroni.
It's messed up that he knows.
Let's light this candle!
Who's ready
for some Kickpunching?
Actually, we decided
to watch Runaway instead.
Tom Selleck fights
mechanical spiders.
What?
No, no, you can't do that.
We just watched Kickpuncher.
We have to see Kickpuncher 2.
I have so many
unanswered questions.
No, I wanna watch Tom Selleck
fight mechanical spiders.
Yes!
My brother died
on the set of that movie.
One of the mechanical spiders
just went haywire
and tore him to pieces.
And Tom Selleck
just stood there.
He just stood there
and watched him die.
Okay, then, let's watch
your Kickpuncher 2 then.
ABED: Yeah. Okay.
Sorry for your loss.
Yeah. That's messed up, dude.
Kickpuncher 2.
KICKPUNCHER:
My punches were only
as strong as my punches.
And then things changed.
Change?
Time to change the channel.
He's gonna be begging for change
if he keeps making bad movies.
They should change this
to something good.
This movie stinks,
we better change its diaper.
That's change
we can believe in.
Okay, something strange
is happening here.
What do you mean?
I'm making jokes during a movie.
Yeah, but you're doing it
with the speed and determination
of the incomparable
Robin Williams.
Maybe I'm just that brilliant.
I think you came prepared.
Dude, even I know
you're lame.
And I'm a tenured professor
sitting in a beanbag chair.
You're not a professor.
Shut up, man.
Fine, you got me!
I did a little advanced work.
Pathetic? No.
I'll tell you what's pathetic.
You all sitting here making fun
of other people's work.
You don't feel good
about yourselves,
you have to tear down
everything around you.
What's the matter?
Mama Chang didn't breastfeed?
She read in a book
it wouldn't make a difference.
PIERCE:
You all sicken me.
And I will no longer participate
in your destructive,
negative behavior.
Pierce, that was deep.
And total BS.
Yeah, this isn't about us.
This is a deflection.
You can't get a genuine laugh.
That, in itself, is a laugh!
I know I'm funny.
I don't need any of you
to validate me.
Hm.
Oh! Oh!
[ALL LAUGH]
Oh, I'm sorry.
PIERCE:
Biggest laugh of the night.
[ALL LAUGH]
Then I was gonna say,
"It's a good day to be gay."
[GROUP LAUGHS]
Annie.
We're sorry. We were worried
about your well-being.
I guess we feel like
we're sort of all a family.
And Jeff and I are like
your Greendale parents.
You're not my mom, Britta.
She would never wear boots
that go up that high.
And what about respecting me
as an adult and as a friend?
Huh, you want to be treated
as an adult and a friend?
Try not dating
your friend's ex-boyfriend.
Find your own man.
Oh, my.
But you don't like Vaughn.
No, I don't!
But I also don't like seeing him
with anyone else. Ta-da!
I asked you if you cared
and you said no.
Fine. I cared.
I'm a girly girl.
I like boys and I don't like it
when they're mean to me.
I don't like it
when they stop kissing me
and start kissing my friends.
I'm not that cool.
I'm not Juno,
okay, homeslice?
This is what it was about?
You were jealous?
Oh, please, you can't tell me
that you weren't jealous
that Vaughn had
his hippie hands
all over
your debate/make-out partner.
What are you insinuating?
I took that kiss for the team.
What?
Yeah.
That kiss wasn't for pleasure.
It was strategic and joyless.
What? Yeah.
You did get weirdly specific
when you were describing
Annie's body.
More specific than the stuff
you told me about Britta?
ANNIE &amp; BRITTA:
What?
Does anyone get specific
about me?
Check your e-mail.
I'll mark you as spam.
Who the hell is Pam?
When you guys first came in,
we were as wholesome and healthy
as the family in Brady Bunch.
And now we're as dysfunctional
and incestuous as the cast
of The Brady Bunch.
I agree with Abed,
this is getting creepy.
No more creepy than when
Jeff wears tight jeans
and you say, "I'd like to slap
those buns on the grill."
BOTH: What?
SHIRLEY: I don't talk like that.
Second of all, where I'm from,
it's perfectly normal for women
to talk about their male
friends' backsides.
You don't see me
saying anything crazy
about Abed and Troy's weird
little relationship.
BOTH: They're just jealous.
All right.
Maybe we're not a family.
Maybe it's more complicated.
Because unlike a real family,
there's nothing
to stop any one of us
from looking at any of the
others as a sexual prospect.
[♪♪♪]
[BOTH GASP]
Why are we even talking
about this?
Because you started having sex
with Britta's ex-boyfriend.
What? We haven't even kissed.
That doesn't mean
you're not having sex.
Vaughn told me he'd take things
as slowly as I wanted.
He likes me for who I am
and I like him.
[GUITAR PLAYING
AND MAN SINGING IN DISTANCE]
You guys hear that?
[HUMMING]
Annie.
Vaughn.
Britta.
Hi.
Old man river.
Eat me.
Did you get my messages?
No.
I threw my phone into the river.
I thought that, "You know,
if I can't be with her,
"who am I gonna call?"
And then I thought, my landlord,
and my sister, and you.
Anyway, I've been doing
a lot of soul searching,
and this is something
I really need to say.
♪ I see you when you smile
And I want to sing a song ♪
♪ But then I write the words ♪
♪ And they always
Come out wrong ♪
♪ They come out wrong ♪
♪ I feel it in my fingers ♪
♪ I feel it in my toes ♪
♪ But then the words
Get frozen ♪
♪ In my mouth like Eskimos ♪
♪ I like your nose ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Annie ♪
♪ Annie's song ♪
His songs are dumber than he is.
Yeah, but they're honest.
I'll be right here.
[LAUGHS]
Vaughn wants to show me a cloud
that looks like a pumpkin.
[CHUCKLES]
If that's okay.
Annie, it's more than okay.
Please date Vaughn.
Or anyone else
outside this creepy circle.
I wouldn't hang out with
you guys if you were creepy.
Trust me, I have good taste.
[♪♪♪]
VAUGHN:
Oh, you smell
like boysenberries.
So just to be clear, I don't
have a shot with any of you?
Ugh.
Oh, my God.
[♪♪♪]
VAUGHN:
I'm dizzy.
[IN ROBOT VOICE]
I am Kickpuncher.
My cyber punches
have the power of kicks.
[GRUNTING]
I am Punchkicker,
meet your match.
[♪♪♪]
[IN WOMAN'S VOICE]
I love you, Kickpuncher.
The only thing
beyond the reach of my fists
is humanity.
Uh-mm.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
You sure Britta
couldn't do your part?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I asked her,
she wasn't available.
Let's go film
the sex scene.