PELTON [OVER PA]:
It's Valentine's week,
when the Greendale Human Being
is the Cupid Being,
delivering your gift
to that special someone.
But remember, Cupid's face
is magic marker on nylon,
so love is not only blind
but also dizzy
and a little belligerent.
I'm chaperoning
tomorrow's dance.
You should come.
Maybe your study buds will go.
What's the blonde's name?
Bitter, Butter, Beetlejuice?
Britta. She says Valentine's Day
ritualizes a connection
between affection and candy
so girls can learn
the ropes of prostitution.
Translation, no date.
I'm gonna join you
at that dance.
But as a novice boyfriend,
could I get a map
of the minefield known as
women's Valentine expectations?
Every day of the year,
I want you to do
what makes you happy.
Tomorrow, I'm gonna be happy
spending the night
with an insatiable
statistics professor.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
MAN [ON RECORDING]:
It's the Registrar's Office.
Seems you're wrong
paying tuition
with airline miles.
We're gonna need a check--
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Message deleted.
BRITTA [SLURRING]:
Jeff Winger, I am calling you.
[BRITTA MOANS]
Oh, yeah.
You're probably, whatever.
So, what's up? Ha-ha!
Oh, it's the Cupid Being.
SHIRLEY:
Ooh!
Now it has arrows. That's safe.
It's from that cook
with beard in the cafeteria.
I guess when he said,
"I'm gonna get you,"
he meant chocolates.
ANNIE:
Aww. A flower from Vaughn.
He's away on a vision quest.
You got something, Abed?
Another muffin basket
from another actress
who wants to be in my next film.
Does that work?
Meryl Streep has two Oscars
because of her baking.
That's sarcasm
but I forgot to inflect.
[SARCASTICALLY]
This sounds way more like
sarcasm.
Inflection is so interesting.
That big bag at the bottom.
Is that for me?
Anything in there for Troy?
Troy Barnes.
Barnes, comma, Troy?
Who cares about getting things?
It destroys the true meaning
of Valentine's Day.
The birth of St. Valentine's.
Oh, good. Now it has arrows.
That's safe.
Sorry I'm late.
ANNIE: It's okay.
You look very early.
Oh, God, I'm really late.
Yes, you are.
Yeah. See you later.
That's all right.
We'll see you.
Can I get you something?
Water? Smelling salts?
An alibi for
Cobain's suicide?
No, but you could help yourself
to a shorter forehead,
a non-Keebler nose,
and shutting up.
Hmm. That stings.
I mean, not the words.
The clouds of bourbon vapor
forming them.
A girlfriend from
my anarchist days was in town
and we drank. Everything.
Yeah. And then you said,
"I should call Jeff."
Yeah, because the first thing
I do when I'm having fun
is think about--
BRITTA [ON RECORDING]:
Jeff Winger, I am calling you.
You're probably...whatever.
So, what's up?
The drunk dial.
So much subtext.
So much intrigue.
So much of what the kids
are calling BCI.
That's, uh,
Booty Call Implication.
[JEFF LAUGHING]
Oh.
What happened to Britta?
Justice.
Having spent the year denying
her attraction to me
just to be alternative,
Britta called me
at 3 a.m. just to ask,
"What's up?"
A drunk dial? Was it BCI?
Booty call with a capital B.
Mm.
This can't be good.
It's no biggie.
We give
each other crap all the time.
Well, that's the point.
What crap can she give now
that you hold the cards?
You shifted balance
like in sitcom
when one
sees another naked.
Is that really
a sitcom staple?
[SARCASTICALLY]
No, I have no idea what I'm
talking about. I never watch TV.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
CHANG:
Now, we all know
that in English,
the rooster says
"cock-a-doodle-doo."
In Español, the gallo says:
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
What? I'm teaching.
[CUPID MOANS]
Ah-ha! I knew
you were holding back.
Oh! It's from the girl
I'm dating.
Yeah, I met her in biology.
She was looking for geology
and misread the sign.
I said, "We do not study
countries in here."
Yeah, she's--
She's dumb, but-- But sweet.
Yeah, mine's from Danielle.
She's, uh-- Uh--
A lovely lady
in my marketing class.
We're sleeping together.
They sound
like very lucky ladies.
Yeah, they're not made up.
Beep-beep! Oh, my God,
what's going on? Beep!
My bull crap meter's
going crazy.
[BEEPING]
[YELLING]
It's these presents
you've sent yourselves
to make it look like
you have girlfriends.
That's ridiculous.
This is obviously
your handwriting, Mr. Tremor.
And yours is signed,
"Love, Troy"?
I tell you, this is the most
pathetic thing
I've ever seen here.
[ALL LAUGHING]
CHANG:
Oh, my God!
Look at him over there,
cutting the gristle
off his steak
as ruthlessly as he cut off
Troy and Pierce's dignity.
Ew! Now he's
eating the gristle.
I'm so sick of Chang.
Always tearing people down,
making them feel horrible.
Somebody needs to humiliate him
the way he humiliated our boys.
Mustache, get me a juice box.
Now!
ANNIE:
And that somebody is us.
[♪♪♪]
You can vomit onto this food
because it already
smells like it.
Ha! Yeah, totally.
[LAUGHS]
My law firm went on a retreat
to Disney World once,
and I got so drunk
that I got into a fight
with animatronic
Ben Franklin.
Why are you telling me this?
Well, the point is
that when I'm sober,
I don't secretly hate
Ben Franklin
or even think about him,
so you drunk dialing me?
It's not like a big deal.
My God. You're pitying me now.
You're acting weird.
I'll talk to you in class,
okay?
Just leave me alone
till then.
[♪♪♪]
[BEEPING]
What is going on here?
My doody meter's going crazy.
Okay, cut, cut, cut.
Leo, I'm not feeling it.
I need to believe you're holding
an imaginary doody meter.
The problem is not me.
It's you and your stupid script.
Idiot.
That's the anger. Use it.
Wow.
One Papa John's commercial
he thinks
he's Christian Bale.
Look, uh, you were right.
Britta is totally weird
around me.
It does feel
I saw her naked.
It's a resonant premise.
Tony saw Angela naked
on Who's the Boss?
And did Tony do
something to fix that?
I don't know. I could never
get past the opening credits.
But when Chandler
saw Rachel naked on Friends,
to even the score Rachel needed
to see Chandler's penis.
All right.
I'll show Britta my penis.
Don't waste my time.
I lose my Chang
to Cub Scouts in 20 minutes.
So what? To even the score,
I have to drunk dial her?
Isn't that absurdly simplistic?
Would it even work?
Maybe. Oh.
No room for error.
She'd have to believe
it was real.
Have you ever acted drunk?
[SLURRING]
I can totally do it.
I'm fine. I can drive.
I can totally drive right now.
Give me my keys.
That's enough.
No, hold on a second.
All right.
[SOBBING]
I don't care.
No, seriously, give me my keys.
Okay, that's a wrap, people.
I want you to be at my place
at 4 so we can work on this.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Well, no, I can't do that.
Here's why.
Dumbest idea ever.
You know Britta's weakness.
She cuts and runs.
You do this half-assed and fail,
she may leave and we lose her.
That's not gonna happen.
Not on my watch.
That's a deal breaker.
Saddle up.
Sorry I lost my cool.
Just quit smoking.
Kid's gonna be a star.
He's a young
"the Asian guy from Lost."
Try it again.
Come on. You're a big guy.
Action.
[IMITATES DIALING PHONE]
Hey, Britta.
Your call got me thinking,
and thinking got me drinking.
Stop. That was terrible.
What?
Mm-mm.
I can get drunk alone
if that's what helps people act.
Well, that's your problem.
You've been acting whole life.
It's time to pass that act up
and find the actor playing you.
Oh, they are gonna
love you in California.
Do you like Britta?
Sure, who doesn't?
Over half the people
that meet her.
They can be put off
by her vacuous mannequin face,
and her Jodie Foster severity.
But you're different.
Uh, you know.
She's no barrel of monkeys.
She-- She wants everyone to be
honest but she lies to herself.
She's seen the world
but doesn't get it.
She has more fights about
stuff that doesn't matter
than a YouTube comment section.
She's passionate, which I find
stupid but entertaining.
Attractive?
It was only attraction at first
because she bothered
to play hard to get.
I'm happy with Michelle.
Slater is low maintenance.
Mm. The lowest.
Britta, irritating,
impossible, unpredictable.
She didn't like you.
It felt useless to like her.
Slater likes you how you are,
expects nothing.
You're safe from change.
And passion.
Watch it.
Watch what?
A phony drunk-dial
soaked in phony pity
that insults Britta
even more?
Or a believable performance
informed by feeling?
You know, I am sure
you're a good director,
but you are a horrible
drinking buddy.
I mean, I can't feel things
with you studying me
like a beige praying mantis.
You're right.
I thought you never drank.
Scorsese drank with De Niro.
It's not for me.
It's for the audience.
[BOTH SPEAK IN POLISH]
[KARLA DEVITO'S
"WE ARE NOT ALONE" PLAYING]
♪ Things look clear
In black and white ♪
♪ The living color
Tends to dull our sight ♪
♪ Like dynamite ♪
♪ Just imagine my surprise ♪
♪ When I looked into your eyes
And saw ♪
♪ Through your disguise ♪
♪ If we dare
Expose our hearts ♪
♪ Just to feel
The purest parts ♪
♪ That's when
Strange sensations ♪
♪ Start to grow ♪
♪ We are not alone ♪
♪ Find out
When your cover's blown ♪
♪ There'll be somebody there ♪
♪ To break your fall ♪
♪ We are not alone ♪
♪ 'Cause when you cut down
To the bone ♪
[LAUGHS]
[MOANS]
All right, class,
turn to page-- Whoa.
Looks like the law firm
of Seacrest and Slumdog
is taking the day off.
Ooh. Another special delivery
from Troy and Pierce's
imaginary lovers?
[CHANG CHUCKLES AND SNORTS]
Wait a minute.
That one's for me.
[LAUGHS]
All right. Oh, yeah.
Wow. It's from Princeton.
They want to make me
associate professor
of the Spanish Department?
They're telling me
I can name my price? Oh, my God.
At Princeton? Come on.
You two idiots
really thought
I'd fall for this, huh?
This is your pathetic attempt
to punish me
for humiliating you.
But we didn't do it.
Save it.
As punishment,
because you two obviously
don't have any girlfriends,
escort me
to the Valentine's Dance
wearing elegant
ladies' pantsuits.
[LAUGHING]
Yeah, right.
[MOCK LAUGHTER]
You'll do it
or you fail.
You can't do that.
Have you met me?
I mean it.
Tonight you are my bitches.
[♪♪♪]
JEFF:
Holy crap.
Abed.
Abed?
[GRUNTING]
It's 3:00.
What happened?
The last thing I remember
is you were dancing
like that girl in the movie
Kids In Detention?
Breakfast Club?
Dear God.
What have you done to me?
Wait, did I call Britta?
Where's my phone?
Got it.
You made two outgoing calls.
One to Britta,
one to your girlfriend.
I don't remember either of them.
Neither do I.
[♪♪♪]
I don't remember
the name of the girl
in The Breakfast Club.
Mary.
Margaret.
Molly Ringworm?
You broke me.
I still can't believe
I'm a size 14.
I know the 12 was a little tight
but I could have pulled it off.
You guys really going through
with this?
We have to. He'll fail us.
We're gonna find out
who wrote that. We have leads.
It was written on
fake Princeton letterhead.
So whoever wrote it,
worked at Princeton,
ran out of stationary,
and didn't have time
to go to store.
Um, you guys?
Uh-uh! Uh.
What?
Women's sizes run slimmer.
I'm sure you're a 12 everywhere
that it counts.
I'll take every little victory
I can get right now.
Thanks.
Hmm. You look about ready
to marry Courtney Love.
[CHUCKLES]
That's the reverse of
my zinger from before.
Please stop shouting,
all right?
I feel like that person
in the TV show.
Do you remember calling me
last night?
Yeah. Why?
Are we cool?
Oh, yeah.
Have a seat, Drunky Brewster.
Let's study.
Balance restored, I guess.
Movie reference.
[DANCE MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Hey there.
Happy Valentine's Day.
I've been calling you.
Yeah, I know.
I figured I'd let it go
to voicemail
in case you had
the wrong number again.
Elaborate?
You don't remember
calling me 4 in the morning
and hanging up when you realized
I wasn't Britta?
I guess not.
Michelle.
Michelle, um,
I was trying to call Britain
to order you toffees.
Now that might sound dumb,
but I needed to open with it
to make truth less ridiculous.
Two nights ago,
Britta drunk-dialed me,
and it embarrassed her
and made her sad,
and the only way for her
to get her power back
was for me to get
believably drunk
and leave her an
equally embarrassing message.
It sure seems
like you and Britta are friends
the way my mom's pool cleaner
was my uncle.
Have you had sex with her?
Not even a little.
What doesn't make sense
is that you did all this work
to put a smile on her face
but can't pick up ice cream
for Law and Order night
because it feels too marriage-y.
First of all, Chubby Hubby?
I mean, could you pick
a scarier flavor?
Let's talk about this later.
I need to chaperone something.
[THE PAPARAZZI KIDS'
"GOING CRAZY" PLAYING]
♪ Pow-pow, we're here ♪
♪ Everybody
Stay up on the tip ♪
♪ 'Cause they love it
When the bass knock ♪
♪ And I love it
When the bass kick ♪
♪ Everybody feel it
In your soul ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh
You never know ♪
♪ If you knock the phone
And let me go ♪
♪ Everybody hitting
The dance floor ♪
♪ So, so incredible ♪
♪ So beat the boys
Gone wild ♪
There he is. Oh.
You know, I thought
I'd be embarrassed.
Now I'm just scared.
I am seriously reconsidering
how much I want this credit.
Remember what we said?
Never let him see us cry.
Right.
Okay, one, two--
Wait.
Keep your coats on.
We're the ones
that sent the letter.
What?
You work--
You work at Princeton?
We were mad at him
for humiliating you.
Well, nice fix, Tweedledum
and even Tweedlerdum.
Look, we're gonna tell Chang
the truth,
and we'll pay the price.
TROY:
Wait.
We can't make you do that.
No, he's right.
We gotta get out
of these pantsuits
then you can put them on.
TROY:
Look, Pierce, this whole thing
started because
you and I were ashamed
that we didn't have ladies
that cared about us.
And the good news is
we obviously do.
The bad news is
that it makes it our manly duty
to protect them tonight.
Oh!
That's nice,
but we really
can't let you do that. It's--
No, he's right. He's right.
Step aside.
SHIRLEY: Oh.
Let's handle this like men.
Yeah.
[WHISTLES]
Whoo. Ladies.
They're gonna be okay?
CHANG:
Get in my Mercedes.
Just look away, baby.
Just look away.
♪ 'Cause I love it
When the bass knock ♪
♪ And I love it
When the bass kick ♪
♪ 'Cause I love it
When the bass knock ♪
♪ And I love it
When the bass kick ♪
♪ 'Cause I love it
When the bass knock ♪
♪ And I love it
When the bass kick ♪
Whoa.
Looking for someone?
Uh, yeah.
Slater.
Heh.
Very funny.
When you called me last night
and invited me to the dance,
I was shocked.
And thrilled.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
No. No.
Look, I'm sorry.
Uh, I don't-- I don't remember
asking you to the dance.
I don't remember anything.
Now Slater knows
all the drunk-dialing stuff,
and I'm in the doghouse.
If she finds out about this,
it's over.
So, again, I am sorry.
I am so, so sorry.
And you are messing with me
right now, aren't you?
I knew
you didn't remember anything
from that phone call last night.
You got dressed up
just to see me sweat?
Oh, believe me.
You're worth it.
Sorry. Just chaperoning.
Enjoy the dance.
Wait, Michelle.
Jeff, what's left to say?
Uh... I-- I don't know.
I--
BRITTA: I do.
He said it last night.
[PHONE BEEPS]
JEFF [ON RECORDING]:
So look, I am really
into Michelle.
And I don't wanna screw it up.
She's a perfect girlfriend.
And I want you to be
as happy as me
because you're, like,
my favorite friend, so--
[JEFF LAUGHING ON RECORDING]
I'm sorry.
Abed just made a turtle face.
In his defense,
Abed's turtle face is funny.
Thanks, Britta.
Yeah, thanks.
Yeah.
That was the first 20 seconds
of a 40-minute message.
Very informative.
Happy Valentine's Day,
perfect boyfriend.
Yeah, that's me.
Man, I can't wait to
get out of these outfits.
Oof! I know, yeah.
What are you doing?
I'm parked over here.
Oh, uh, well... Uh...
[LAUGHS]
Come on.
Um, what the hell is this?
We're going to get
frozen yogurt.
I'm not gay.
They close in seven minutes.
I could have driven you.
You said he hated fro-yo.
Just drive.
Slut!
[HORN HONKING]