[♪♪♪]
[GROUP CHATTERING]
Good morning, everybody.
SHIRLEY: Hi, Jeff.
I brought bagels.
Oh, I'd love a bagel.
The perfect beginning
for my first day
of billiards class.
SHIRLEY: Oh.
Did you pick an outfit
to look sexy shooting pool?
Shirley, I have no idea
what you are talking about.
SHIRLEY: Ooh.
ALL: Oh!
Thirteen.
Oh, great, so much for baggles.
So much for what?
BRITTA: The baggles.
You dropped them on the floor.
Uh, they're called "bagels."
Uh, I lived in New York, Troy.
I know what a baggle is.
What the hell is wrong
with you?
What?
You say "bagel" wrong.
I say it the same as you.
Say it again.
Baggle.
[ALL LAUGHING
EXCEPT BRITTA &amp; ABED]
Can we just keep studying?
We're on page 258.
What "padge" was that?
SHIRLEY: Two-five-tee-eight.
Whoa. Check this out.
Uh-oh.
Oh, it's a drawing of Abed
with hearts all around it.
Strictly speaking, Troy,
the Bible condemns
this level of friendship.
I didn't draw that.
I bought that book used.
It must have been
whoever had it last.
Obviously, it's a girl
who has a crush on Abed.
This is so romantic.
It's like The Notebook,
except instead of Alzheimer's,
Abed has--
Ahem. Mm-hm.
--someone who likes him.
Well, whoever she is,
she's fat.
These thick lines
were drawn with a heavy hand.
We gotta find this person
for Abed.
Unless it's a boy,
then we find him for Jesus.
But either way,
this is going to be fun.
[SHIRLEY &amp; ANNIE GIGGLING]
SHIRLEY: Cute little face.
Gotta find that girl.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
Adios.
CLASS: Adios.
Guys, class is over.
I'm trying to
get you to leave.
CLASS:
Oh.
Pick that up.
Señor Chang?
We're trying to figure out
whose Spanish book this was
before Troy's.
[CHANTING]
Jenny Adams.
Oh.
Oh, come on.
If all Chinese were psychic
you would have started using
birth control centuries ago.
Her name's in the front
of the book, morons.
Yay.
He's right.
Them I understand.
But how did you not think
of that?
I may have been thrown off
by Britta's pronunciation
of "bagel."
How do you pronounce bagel?
I don't.
Come on
Baggle.
Ugh, you're the worst.
So we have a name.
Jenny Adams.
Cool.
See, it's a fat girl's name.
Might as well be Gravy Jones.
Pierce, it doesn't matter
what she looks like.
This will be great for Abed.
It will?
Aren't you excited
about talking to her?
I wasn't planning on it.
What?
Guys, come on, you heard Abed.
He's not interested. Drop it.
You need to mind
your own business.
Abed, you need to get
with this girl, immediately.
Yeah?
Abed, for guys like you,
this kind of opportunity
only comes around once in a--
While.
It's important to date
in college, Abed.
It's a time of freedom
and exploration.
A time
when a simple pillow fight
between two innocent girls
could turn to a steamy night
of unbridled lust.
Britta knows all about it.
ABED: Okay. Cool.
You guys are gonna
Can't Buy Me Love me?
We're gonna what you?
Gonna Can't Buy Me Love me.
Transform me
from zero to hero, geek to chic.
Oh, he wants us
to Love Don't Cost a Thing him.
Oh.
Can't Buy Me Love was the
remake for white audiences.
That's so uncomfortable
when they do that.
I can't believe
it doesn't insult them.
All right, nobody here
is Can't Buy Me Love-ing
or Love Don't Cost a Thing-ing
anyone.
Because we've all seen enough
after-school specials
and Fat Albert to know...
Oh.
...that Abed only needs
to be himself.
Sure glad
there are no old people here.
This conversation would probably
be total gibberish to them.
Jeff's unprecedentedly right
about this.
Abed, when we find this girl,
you're gonna approach her
just the way you are
because that's good enough.
Yeah, then you can
take her to a nice deli
and treat her to a baggle.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
Oh, yeah.
ALL:
Hey, nice shooting.
Good clean strokes.
Thanks.
Form a line, please.
My name is Coach Bogner.
Welcome to the Art of Pool,
which is a Phys Ed class.
Which means
that you have to wear the
proper equipment at all times.
So suit up. See you back
on the felt in five.
You're gonna look
like an ass in those.
Shut up, Leonard.
I talked to your son
on Family Day.
I know all
about your gambling.
Touché.
All right, everybody
just hang out and be casual.
My sources tell me
that Jenny Adams is the blond
who's reading right
over there.
Whoa!
That's her?
She's pretty.
Which is not a surprise at all,
Abed.
Okay, Abed, we're gonna be here
for moral support.
Go over there,
do your thing.
Okay.
BRITTA: Remember, be yourself.
Got it. Cool.
BRITTA: Great.
[CLICKING TONGUE]
TROY: Abed.
Yeah?
What are you doing?
I'm being myself.
Go be yourself
by Jenny.
I wouldn't go over there.
How do you know that?
A lifetime of observation.
You think
there's a version of yourself
that might go over there?
Absolutely.
ANNIE: Could you be him?
Okay.
[HISSING]
BOTH:
Oh, oh!
What the hell was that?
A different version of me.
I think it was a vampire.
If this is gonna turn ugly,
I can't be here.
I'm a two-striker.
No, Pierce, please,
hang on.
Abed,
will you excuse us, please?
Yeah.
Look, I know
that we're all good people.
And we believe that people
should be themselves.
But if Abed is himself,
he's gonna die alone.
And if we let him
be someone else--
Be right back.
[HISSING]
I'm out of here.
[♪♪♪]
Mm-mm.
Not gonna happen, buddy.
[GROUP CHATTERING]
MAN:
Oh, my God,
there's a midget on stilts.
[GROUP CHUCKLING]
[MAN WHISTLES]
[GROUP LAUGHS]
You're not in uniform.
Yeah, about that.
We seriously have to wear shorts
to play pool?
If you play in this class.
It's regulation.
Regulation pool
or regulation you?
Do you have something
against playing pool
with a full range of motion
and optimal comfort?
I'm comfortable in my clothes.
I bet you are.
I'm sorry?
I said
I bet you're
comfortable dressed
like a model instead
of an athlete,
sipping martinis,
smoking,
instead of keeping your game
on the table.
Hey, man, you're implying
I'm some sort of pool poser
because I don't wanna wear
a bathing suit.
You're the weird one.
That's weird, not me.
Nobody plays pool like that.
Yeah, what do you call this?
I call that
your personal business, okay?
And I call this class
the desecration
of America's coolest sport.
Yeah. I-- See, right there.
"Coolest sport."
Okay, I want everybody to know
what's going on here.
This hipster
is dropping this class
because he cares more
about what he looks like
than how he's playing.
Oh, please.
You're the one
with the rules about clothes.
And, by the way,
I could kick your ass
all over that table.
Oh, is that a challenge?
Huh? Because if you
play me in pool,
you play me in shorts.
And if you can't do that,
my point's already made.
[STAMMERING]
I don't have anything
to prove to you or...
Look, you're stupid.
This is stupid.
Pool in shorts is stupid.
Vanity,
thy name is...his name.
WOMAN:
Bye.
It's first day,
I didn't catch it.
Okay, Abed, we know that
you wouldn't approach a girl.
But if you don't learn how,
you won't get Jenny.
And you got two days.
Then I'm going after her.
ANNIE: Pierce.
What, I'm incentivizing him.
Also, if she's into Abed,
let's face it,
anybody could hit that.
I need to change who I am
to someone more likeable.
No, sweetie,
it's not about changing.
It's about learning.
Learning to change?
No, it's--
Good grief, clear
the chickens off the runway.
I'll be the bad guy.
Yes, Abed,
you need to be someone else.
Someone who eventually
gets a girlfriend.
Because I can't think
of anything more frightening
than a half-Polish,
half-Arab virgin in his 30s.
One way or the other,
that story ends with explosion.
Let's try a practice run.
Annie, you sit here,
and be a girl.
Abed, you take a run at her.
Let's see what you got.
Okay.
Hmm.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
What are you reading?
Pride and Prejudice.
So you're familiar
with two sins.
How about a third?
Oh.
[♪♪♪]
I don't think
we're allowed to smoke in here.
Then you picked
the wrong outfit,
didn't you?
Abed, what are you doing?
Don Draper from Mad Men.
What'd you think?
Weird.
Awesome.
Put your tongue in her ear.
I liked it.
Don't be him.
He cheats on his wife.
Be somebody nice
like Mike Brady.
He always had that housekeeper
throwing herself at him.
He never made a move on her.
Don't be Mike Brady.
He's not sexy.
You should be like Jo
from Facts of Life.
But you know, the dude version.
I knew it.
You should be like Calvin.
His best friend was a tiger,
he went on dope adventures.
Anything stood in his way,
he just peed on it.
Calvin Coolidge?
Don Draper
was clearly the sexiest--
TROY:
And the worst thing about it,
is like that Calvin...
What are you guys doing?
They're teaching me
how to be someone else.
Oh, for God's sake.
What did I tell you guys?
[IMITATING JEFF]
Oh, for God's sakes,
do whatever you want.
Leave each other alone.
Whoa, that's a good Jeff.
How'd you do that?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Ten percent Dick Van Dyke,
20 percent Sam Malone,
40 percent Zach Braff in Scrubs,
and 30 percent Hilary Swank
in Boys Don't Cry.
Zach Braff?
Sorry.
Abed, what if you just
did Jeff for Jenny?
[AS JEFF]
Uh-- And your point is?
Look, I don't want
any part of this.
And I can't believe
that you're still doing it
after I already explained
the obvious lesson
smacking you in the face.
Why aren't you
in billiards class?
Because I don't look cool
in shorts!
Oh! Whoa!
Okay.
Because I'm not cool in shorts!
Now, that's good.
TROY: That was really good.
[♪♪♪]
I don't wanna spoil the ending
but, uh,
pride ends up with prejudice.
That's funny.
ABED: I know.
Stick with me, you get a laugh.
That's the Abed guarantee.
I feel like
I've seen you before.
It's working.
I know.
I get that a lot
from art students.
I'm told I have a face
made for sketching.
I'd rather think
it was made for kissing.
How about for punching?
Huh?
[♪♪♪]
What are you doing
hitting on my girlfriend, ugly?
This is awkward.
Oh, my God.
It's a white Abed.
I know. It-- It's like Abed
but employable.
Huh, boss? Let's go, Slumdog.
Oh.
PELTON [ON PA]:
One last Lost and Found
announcement.
Jeff Winger, I've been informed
by Coach Bogner
that you left your panties
in his pool class
so better pick those up.
When is he gonna stop
doing that?
Do you know
that he called me a hipster?
Hipster.
Do hipsters walk around
wearing $300 jeans from Italy?
Can we please talk about Abed?
Thanks to us,
he's heart's been broken.
Well, I hate to say
that I told you so,
so I'll shout it
through cupped hands.
I told you so!
We were only trying to help.
Oh, come on, who are
we kidding? Jeff's right.
Abed was happy being Abed
till we had to sully his mind
with thoughts of love
and romance and vaginas.
Those are the big three.
That's what they call them.
Poor Abed. He was probably
too sad to get out of bed.
Hi.
ANNIE: Abed.
About yesterday--
Oh, yeah.
You guys must be pretty upset.
Why would we be upset?
I know how important it was
for you that I get a girlfriend.
So when Jenny went off
with white Abed,
it must have really hurt.
Ah. It did.
White Abed?
Jenny's boyfriend is a white guy
that's almost
identical to Abed.
It's Joey, that's why
the sketch was in Troy's book.
So does that make Abed
brown Joey?
If you wanna get racist
about it.
You know we just want you
to be happy, right?
Everybody wants me
to be happy.
Everybody wants to help me.
But when they can't,
they get frustrated
and stop talking to me.
Or trick me
into buying them ice cream
then, shove me
into a clothes dryer.
Which I didn't wanna happen
with you guys,
so I wanted to make sure
you felt like you could help me.
The truth is,
lots of girls like me
because I'm pretty adorable.
Mm-hm.
And my aloofness unconsciously
reminds them of their fathers.
I'm more used to them
approaching me.
So we didn't damage
your self-esteem?
Britta, I got self-esteem
falling out of my butt.
That's why I was willing
to change for you,
because when you really
know who you are
and what you like
about yourself
changing for other people
isn't such a big deal.
Abed, you're a god.
If you'll all excuse me,
I have a man to beat in pool
while wearing shorts.
Nice.
Is that code
for going number one
or number two?
Abed, you've inspired me too.
People can mock me
all they want.
I don't care
how I say the word "baggle."
[GROUP LAUGHING]
"Baggle."
She said the word "baggle."
[GROUP CHATTERING]
Hey, nice cross corner, Leonard.
LEONARD: Totally.
I'd like to see Jeff Winger
try that shot
without the benefit
of his stylish clothing.
Oh, would you?
Jeff Winger.
Shouldn't you be
at an Urban Outfitters?
I'll go there later
if I feel like it.
But first,
I have to hand someone
their tightly polyester-swaddled
ass in a game of pool.
CROWD:
Ooh.
Oh, burn.
You wanna talk
about clothes like a girl?
Or use tapered sticks
to hit balls
around a cushioned table
like a man?
Balls, like a man.
MAN: Oh!
Rack them.
I'll break.
Why? Because it looks cool?
I don't know.
You tell me.
[WARREN ZEVON'S
"WEREWOLVES OF LONDON" PLAYING]
MAN:
Yeah.
[MAN WHISTLES]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
♪ I saw a werewolf ♪
♪ With a Chinese menu
In his hand ♪
♪ Walking through the streets
Of Soho in the rain ♪
♪ He was looking for a place
Called Lee Ho Fook's ♪
Get out of the way.
♪ Gonna get a big dish
Of beef chow mein ♪
[CROWD CHEERING]
Shh-shh, boom.
Let me just clean this side
of the table off here.
Oh, okay. There you go.
See that? There you go, yeah.
Yeah. What do you think of that?
You haven't learned anything.
Except how to look cool
playing pool in shorts.
You're wrong, man.
I'm just having a good time
because I love playing pool.
BOGNER:
Liar.
You think you look cool.
Yeah?
Well, how cool is this?
[CROWD GASPS]
Stop projecting your obsession
with clothes onto me
as an excuse for when I beat you
in a game of real pool.
Oh, you wanna play real pool,
huh?
CROWD:
Oh!
I'll play real pool.
Now who doesn't care
how they look?
Me.
Shouldn't you be stopping this?
Soon. Soon.
Just gathering evidence.
[WARREN ZEVON'S "WEREWOLVES
OF LONDON" PLAYING]
Three-to-one against Winger.
Who's on?
[MUTTERS]
Oh!
Yeah!
♪ Who ran amuck in Kent ♪
♪ Lately he's been overheard
In Mayfair ♪
CROWD:
Oh.
You know what, Jeff?
One of us
is about to win this game.
But years from now,
when the story is retold,
all they're gonna remember
is one of us loved clothes
and the other loved
the game.
CROWD:
Ooh.
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMING]
[ALL GROAN]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[♪♪♪]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
MAN: Oh.
WOMAN: Ooh.
CROWD:
Oh!
[ALL CHATTERING]
[♪♪♪]
Yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
[ALL CHEERING]
JEFF:
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah.
You look at me. Look at me.
You beat me.
From now on, you play pool
dressed however you choose.
I choose shorts.
Shorts.
You son of a bitch.
You magnificent son of a bitch.
SHIRLEY:
Oh!
[♪♪♪]
Jeff.
That was awesome.
Let me get in here. Oh!
Okay, you're sweaty.
All right, all right.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Nice game.
Thanks.
Look, I-- I hope
this doesn't sound too forward.
But, um, could you introduce me
to your friend?
[♪♪♪]
You know what? I--
I know that guy's M.O.,
and I think it's better
if you introduce yourself.
Okay.
Hi.
Courtney.
Abed.
Man,
why couldn't I be brown Joey?
Tsk.
[HUMMING]
Hey, Abed.
Hey Troy.
Here's the book I borrowed.
Thank you.
Did you finally
get your own book?
Something like that.
Wait a second.
[SNICKERING]
[GROANS]
It's okay.
Let's have cookies.
Okay.
Mm. Mm.
[LAUGHS]
My cousin's funeral was today.
Oh, was that was today?
I knew there was some reason
I couldn't do this today.
Poor Demitri.