I had to get up so early
for my bus
I caught what Cinemax
gets up to at night.
Subscription cancelled.
I got that for Eddie Murphy,
not stimulation.
Why the bus?
What happened to your minivan?
My ex-husband needed it.
The person he's dating
works at a club
an hour from the city.
I'll play a violin for them
and maybe she can strip to it.
Kind people
are always kind, Britta.
Not just when it's easy.
As we stand,
once again upon the deadline
to drop or add classes,
I hereby present
this semester's Jeff Winger pick
for ultimate blow-off class,
Beginner Pottery.
Your last "blow off" class
ended up teaching me
to live in the moment.
Which I will always regret
and never do again.
This one's different.
I researched.
You don't have
to make a good pot.
You get an art credit
for participation.
This class is like a redhead
that drinks Scotch
and loves Die Hard.
I suggest
you all get her number.
Ahoy!
Guess which class
I signed up for.
Singing with Tennille?
[LAUGHTER]
Oh, ho ,hey.
Sailing.
The nearest water
is hours away.
Leagues, Abed.
We don't measure water
by hours.
It's a one-week intensive
that gives you hands-on
experience on a real boat
right here in the parking lot.
I'd rather learn boats
than pots.
I was gonna take a class to
put together a dating profile.
But sailing in the parking lot
is less pathetic.
A black person on a sail boat?
I gotta see this. I'm in.
How about you?
You wanna sail with us?
There's black people.
Two.
[♪♪♪]
JEFF:
All right.
Hello, ladies.
What you guys making,
big balls here?
Oh, yeah.
You guys getting dirty?
Nice.
What are you looking at?
All right.
Hey, Laura Ingalls.
Home Depot guy.
Who's making pots, huh?
Let's participate this thing.
Let's do this.
I don't know
why you're laughing.
I do wanna make
my mom an ashtray.
Okay.
[RICH LAUGHING]
[CHUCKLES]
Hello, my precious blueberries.
Hello.
Hi.
All right, spin those wheels
and play with some clay.
Now, there's one
and only one rule in this class.
I will tolerate no reenacting,
whether it's ironic or sincere,
of the Patrick Swayze-Demi Moore
pottery scene in Ghost.
Ever since that movie
was released in 1990,
I have seen
every conceivable variation
of what I call ghosting.
This can be guy-on-girl,
girl-on-guy.
The hilarious guy-on-guy.
[GROUP LAUGHING]
[IMITATES GUNSHOT]
So since it never stopped,
I had to adopt
a zero-Ghost-tolerance policy.
If you hum three notes
of that Righteous Brothers song,
with God as my witness,
I will come at you
with everything I've got, okay?
Let's have a great time.
[♪♪♪]
I'm making falafel. Not edible.
Mm.
What are you making?
A vase.
Hey, guys.
Yep?
Look what I made.
A participant badge.
[GASPS]
I don't know how.
I just stuck my hands
into the clay and it happened.
You look at me.
You have a gift.
ABED:
Jeff's competitive side
had come out before,
he had even displayed envy.
But on that first day
of Pottery class--
Abed.
Yeah?
What did we discuss?
No voiceover. I'm sorry.
It is kind of a crutch.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ I can't count
The reasons I should stay ♪
[BOTTLE CLINKING]
Never been on a boat.
I didn't know what to wear.
TROY:
Yeah, it's intimidating.
We're in Pierce's world now.
He's got all the boat clothes,
and look at him christen.
If that were me,
I would've broken the bottle.
I'm Professor Slaughter.
Welcome aboard
the S.S. Nose Candy,
purchased
through government auction.
Oh, that's nice.
It's not nice.
It's your only weapon
against the sea.
Don't know how to use her,
you're dead.
Together,
you will work as one crew.
You will succeed
or fail as one crew.
Consider this parking lot
the ocean.
Whatever you drop, you lose.
Mishandle the sails,
you capsize and die.
Now, does Little Miss Nice
have a name?
Shirley Bennett.
Well, now you're
Captain Shirley Bennett.
Aw, man.
You will follow her every order.
Oh.
I've never been a captain.
I have.
I commanded a jet ski
through an electrical storm
and only had one casualty.
Jet skis only hold
two people.
Exactly. Saved half the crew.
Pottery is cooler
than I thought.
And harder.
Except for that guy, Rich.
He's like a natural.
I'm worried about the effect
it's having on Jeff.
Yeah, someone call a shrink.
What?
You're usually
the cool one.
Abed, you understand the point
of a blow-off class
is to blow it off?
Not to be cool
at making important mud pies.
Not willing to admit
he's talented?
No, because he's not.
If I were to make
an effort,
you'd think
I was the cat's pajamas.
"Cat's pajamas"?
Okay, Pierce.
Somebody's mommy
gave him too much praise.
Man, so did someone's
psych teacher.
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
Oh, Señor Chang.
Yes, I was robbed at the YMCA.
Again.
[♪♪♪]
All right, let's do this.
JEFF'S MOM:
Jeff, do you know what you are?
You're special.
You're very special, Jeff.
The most special little boy
in the world.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Take her back to harbor.
SHIRLEY:
Flank the sheets
and trim the headsail.
ALL:
Aye aye.
Eyes on me for a moment.
I don't see students here,
I see seamen.
And I didn't create them.
From the moment you climbed
aboard, I saw seamen inside you.
More importantly,
you've stopped giggling
at the word "seamen."
And that's the mark
of a real seaman.
All right, as you were.
Okay, then, crew,
make fast the topping lift.
I'll get the rope.
[GRUNTS]
Oh, my God.
Damn. He's ghost riding the jib.
[GRUNTS]
Pierce, hang on.
That hat's gone.
Lost at sea.
I might be able to reach it.
it landed on that Hyundai.
I mean, mermaid's car.
Get back on this boat.
No, no, no.
[GRUNTS]
Well, I spoke too soon.
Everybody gets a D.
If I had chosen to hit you
with a storm just then,
you all would have failed.
Get your crew in line, captain.
Permission to speak?
Mm-hm.
You really screwed the pooch
on that one.
And I can't swim.
RICH:
So, you see, ladies,
it's a working fountain.
With a bird.
[IMITATING BIRD CHIRPING]
Jeff! Ready to make some art
in the shape of a vase?
No, can't.
Ooh, ouch.
Let me take a look.
Rich, being good
at Beginner Pottery
doesn't mean
you can heal people.
That's true.
But my medical degree does.
I'm a doctor.
A doctor?
I just take pottery to unwind.
I haven't lost a patient
in five years.
Puts a lot of pressure
on a person.
So the good news is,
neither sprained nor broken.
Oh, thank God.
But I'll have to get
a second opinion
from a guy
in my basket-weaving class.
[LAUGHS]
That's great. That's funny.
Good to see you
getting along with Rich.
What's he like?
He's a ringer.
A what?
You know, a con man,
a grifter, a ringer.
He's an expert potter
who signs up for novice classes
to impress people.
If he wants to impress,
why join a pottery class?
Why not just say,
"Hi, I'm a doctor"?
Because he's crazy.
And fancy jobs
don't impress people.
You weren't impressed
I'm a lawyer.
Anyone can be a lawyer.
You can represent yourself.
You can't do surgery
on yourself.
It's illegal.
You'd get arrested.
And then
you'd get a free lawyer.
Rich showed me
how to make a flared lip
and check for breast lumps.
I don't know how,
and I don't know when,
but one day
that guy is gonna slip up.
And when that happens,
I'll be there to expose him.
Jeff, if your finger's
still bugging you,
just get creative.
I wanna kiss you on the mouth.
I'm sorry?
[♪♪♪]
[CAR ALARM CHIRPS]
Hey, Rich. Hey.
Don't run so fast,
you're among friends.
How you doing, Jeff? What's up?
Not much, nada mucho.
Natalie Merchant.
Just want to thank you
for taking a look at my finger.
Anytime.
Doc Potterywood, I like it.
Have you taken
many pottery classes?
No, this is my first.
Of the year?
Ever.
No pottery at doctor school?
Medical school?
Pottery school.
Pottery school?
Pottery school? How long?
It's kind of weird,
I feel I'm being interrogated,
by someone who doesn't
wanna know anything important.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Oh, hey, New Mexico.
Long way from home.
Yeah. Well, I did my residency
in Santa Fe.
Santa Fe.
Yeah.
Can I give you a lift somewhere?
Oh, no, thanks.
I'm getting there.
[MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
Did you sleep here?
Only for a few hours.
Guess where Rich is from.
Couldn't have been Crazy Town.
You'd gone to school together.
Santa Fe, New Mexico.
Nobody gets out of Santa Fe
without learning to make a pot.
Forty-five percent Hispanic.
Fifth-highest
Native American population.
They eat and breathe clay there.
I think some of this research
is from Wikipedia.
You're mocking me? You?
No, you, fine, go ahead,
mock me.
You're Goldblum-ing.
Goldblum-ing?
[CHUCKLES]
I, uh-- I don't know
what that means.
Look, I have work to do
before class
because I wanna catch Rich
when he slips up.
Who even cares
if he's pretending?
Pottery cares.
Integrity cares.
Look, I don't care.
I just care that he cares.
It's lame that he cares.
Shoelace came untied.
Could happen to anybody.
That's your excuse?
Britta weighs 5 pounds.
Troy can't swim.
I've never seen the ocean.
Uh, I can swim, racist.
Listen to me. On my boat,
the crew comes first.
No single person is above it.
You either shape up
or ship the hell out.
Now I know what the C
in captain stands for.
Crab apple.
I thought you said
kind people were always kind.
Yes. And strong people change.
If the sea was always
still and calm,
nobody would respect her.
I'm like the sea.
Hey.
Cuckoo birds, do you mind?
This is important.
College is where
mental problems activate.
I hope I get
multiple personalities.
I get lonely
in long showers.
[♪♪♪]
SLAUGHTER:
The barometer's dropping.
The temperature is warm,
but we're heading
into a high-pressure flow.
That's a perfect storm.
Reef the mainsail
and furl the jib.
Is that nautical talk
or urban speak?
We have to turn back.
Accidental jibe.
Hit the deck.
[GROANS]
Oh!
Man overboard.
BRITTA:
Pierce is dead!
No, wait.
His stomach is moving.
BRITTA:
Oh, my God. Pierce.
Ugh. That's it. Pull me in.
The storm is overtaking you,
captain.
We don't have time.
I'm trying as hard as I can.
I have skinny arms.
I said, we don't have time.
[♪♪♪]
What? No. Pull--
Wait. Pull me in.
What do you mean, "time"?
That's it.
What? No.
No!
Bring the boom amid ship.
No! No!
What in God's name have we done?
[CRYING]
Hey.
Get out of my parking spot,
dipwad.
Security.
Take an intermediate class
if you're an intermediate.
Don't come in here
making your fear of failure
our problem.
I mean, it's crazy.
It's crazy.
I mean,
he's a crazy person.
[WHISPERING]:
I'm scared.
It's okay.
This is good for him.
He's confronting
his own limitations.
Busted.
Fatal mistake, Richy boy.
You are busted.
I am?
You just used the "throwing
off the hump" method.
That's an advanced pottery
technique, which I know
because last night, I read
the Encyclopedia of Pottery.
What are you talking about?
You are no beginner, Santa Fe.
Hey, what is going on,
my blueberries?
Show him what you did.
No.
I rest my case.
What case?
Throw the freaking hump!
What are you doing? No.
Hey! Hey!
It's the hilarious
guy-on-guy.
One rule I asked you to follow.
One.
Look.
[ANNIE GASPS]
Made before he died.
It's not in bad taste.
Out, Winger.
Fine. That's fine.
[PEOPLE GASP]
Congratulations.
You've failed a class so easy
that people passing
get a contact credit.
♪ Oh, my love ♪
♪ My darling ♪
[SCREAMING]
♪ Touch ♪
♪ Are you still mine? ♪
Pierce. Still have the number
of that investigator you used
when you thought Ross Perot
was sleeping with your mom?
That guy in your class?
Yeah.
Face the facts. This kid's got
talent you just don't have.
How would you know?
It's all over the school.
Great.
Why aren't you
in sailing class?
They drowned me.
Why?
For a better grade.
But weren't we discussing
your flaws, Jeff?
Why are you letting
this guy get to you?
What's really going on?
I made a bad pot.
I always thought that
I was special and different.
And I guess I just have
a really hard time
when I want to be good
at something and I suck.
Uh-huh.
Here, give me a hand.
What are you doing?
I'm going back
to my sailing class.
After they murdered you?
Jeffrey,
when I was born,
I got my umbilical cord
wrapped around my neck,
both arms
and one of my ankles.
Mom said the doctors
stopped delivering me
and just started laughing.
I mean, if I ever let being bad
at something stop me,
I wouldn't even be here.
That thing some men
call failure, I call living.
Breakfast.
And I'm not leaving till
I've cleaned out the buffet.
Now, how about a shove?
[♪♪♪]
Good luck, Pierce.
Don't need it.
Never had it.
Britta,
trim the boom flat.
Troy, sit windward
to heel the boat.
My, the sea
has a worthy opponent.
Oh, my God,
it's Pierce.
[♪♪♪]
Man, that guy's life
is one big joke.
I feel bad for him,
but things have been
smoother since he drowned.
I bet he gets that
all the time.
[GRUNTING]
Oh. Oh. Hey. Hey.
TROY: Oh, my God.
It's going down!
Pierce is going to be
the only person
ever to drown
in a parking lot,
twice.
[LAUGHTER]
Help!
Damn the storm.
We're going after Pierce.
Jump the halyard.
Star-Burns,
man the iron jinny.
There's a man overboard.
That's an order.
PIERCE:
I'm gonna sink.
I'm about to get the only A
I will ever get,
and Pierce isn't even dying.
Bailing.
You don't have to do this.
I know.
But I'd rather be kind
and get stepped on
every once in a while
than be a hard-ass
and turn my back on a friend.
Hoist the mains.
I don't want to go this way.
[♪♪♪]
SHIRLEY:
We're coming, Pierce.
PIERCE:
Help.
SHIRLEY:
How's it looking?
We've gotta go faster.
Okay, come on, Star-Burns.
It's filling with water.
[INAUDIBLE]
[♪♪♪]
It's going down.
Pierce, we're coming.
Dear God. Dear God.
Oh, yes. Oh, Britta.
Troy.
Here you go.
We gotcha.
Okay.
[LAUGHS]
Are you okay?
You all right?
You just steered your boat
into a storm. Any last words?
The sea may be cold
and unforgiving,
but I'm not.
The ship might go down
but at least she'll go down
with honor.
I'll take
your captain's hat
because I'm promoting you
to admiral.
You all get an A.
Oh!
Admiral Shirley. I like that.
It means nothing, really,
the class is over.
But you deserve it.
Somebody has to do this.
I'm king of the--
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Don't ruin a perfect week.
[♪♪♪]
I'm not gonna spoon you again.
I appreciate that.
Yeah, I can't fully explain
my behavior.
I'd love to blame booze
or demon possession--
You know what?
Don't worry about it.
I'm bad at holding grudges.
Well, I'm bad at pottery.
I'm an amateur
pottery enthusiast
trying as hard as I can
at something I suck at.
It's great. And the teacher
said I could stay
if I don't have
any more Ghost bursts.
Fantastic.
Well, good luck.
Don't need it.
JEFF'S MOM:
Jeff, you're a normal person.
There's nothing very special
about you at all.
You're going to be great
at a few things,
but really crappy
at many more.
And that takes a lot
of the pressure off
so you can live
a full, happy life.
And sorry it took me so long
to tell you that,
and it was only
in your imagination.
My bad.
Kind of a sloppy mom.
That's okay, Mom.
Nobody's perfect.
I'm still scared.
RICH'S MOM:
Clay ashtray. You're an idiot.
Why do you have time
to make pottery?
Couldn't you use a little more
practice being a doctor?
Not that it'll ever bring
your brother back to life.
It was supposed to be you
on that roller coaster,
Richard.
It was supposed to be you!
Whoo!
Oh, come on.
Again?
Good grief.