Hey, Britta,
what are you gonna knitta?
Good mood, bad rhyme,
and is that a carb
on your plate?
I got a B on my nutrition final,
and I am celebrating with pie
and a dollop of whipped irony.
Nice. I'm knitting something
for my new cat.
It's been two weeks
since I lost Suzie B,
I figured
it was time to move on.
Not being an animal lover,
I assume it'll nice
to start over with a kitten.
Fresh kitten?
I go to a shelter
and rescue an animal
that genuinely needs
my help, okay?
Why do you think I am knitting
a tiny, little eye patch?
Excuse me. Hi.
We're in high school,
but here for college credit.
Well, all right.
Way to be go-getters.
Thanks.
So we were just wondering.
Can you tell us what you did
in your lives to end up here
so that we don't make
the same mistakes?
Yeah, because if I end up 35
and celebrating a B in nutrition
in community college,
I'll kill myself.
Watch it.
Yeah!
Watch it!
Or what, schmitty?
[LAUGHS]
Schmitty.
You gonna knit me
something sad
in your house full of cats
with no furniture?
Listen, it's a studio apartment,
and knitting is hip.
Winona Ryder knits.
Who?
Schmitty.
Schmits!
[CHUCKLES]
I've done things with my life,
awesome things.
I've been to 14 countries.
I helped build a school
in Kenya.
I once met Sting
at a Cracker Barrel.
Why let a bunch of teenagers
get to you?
I don't even remember
what they said.
It just rolled--
Would you stop
tuning that guitar!
You are 105 years old!
Tell me what you did
with your life to end up here,
so I don't make
the same mistakes!
Excuse me!
But it's springtime,
I thought I might woo chicks.
[STRUMS GUITAR]
♪ No one to watch
While we're kissing ♪
♪ No one to see
While we spoon ♪
♪ Let's take a trip
In my airship ♪
♪ And we'll visit the man
In the moon ♪
Hey, hey, hey!
What the hell!
Hey, what?
Sorry.
Animal House.
A reference my ears applaud.
I couldn't resist.
Smashing the guitar
of someone singing a love song
was on my
college experience list.
Your what?
It's a list of everything
that comprises a successful
first year at college.
"Bond with a group
of lovable misfits."
ABED: Check.
"Take on the school bully.
Make out with
the hottest girl on campus."
Check-a-rooni.
[MOUTHING] You?
The school year
is almost over,
and there's a stuff left
on the list.
I'll help you finish it. I'll be
like your Morgan Freeman.
Like in The Bucket List.
The what?
Stand up for a second.
Uh, come over here.
Stand there.
Okay, turn around.
Okay.
[ALL LAUGH]
What the hell?
Pantsing someone was on my list.
It would've been better
if it were giant hearts.
But I'll take it.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I hope getting pantsed
is on your list.
It is.
[ALL LAUGHING]
What's so funny?
[LAUGHS]
This!
[SHIRLEY GASPS]
Oh! Oh!
[LAUGHING]
Get it?
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ I can't count
The reasons I should stay ♪
[♪♪♪]
Finally.
No, Pierce,
Shirley is way too angry
to talk to you right now.
Yeah, apologize later.
Apologize for what?
She should apologize to me.
She ruined my joke.
MARK:
Oh, my God.
There's a grandpa schlip-schlap.
[IMITATING OLD MAN'S VOICE]
Have you seen my schmitty?
Help, I'm gonna crap my pants.
Oh, seriously, nutrition,
this is your life?
Actually, I was a lawyer.
Looks like that went well.
And hangs with schlip-schlap
and schlap-skank.
Oh, my God!
Is she wearing a Discman?
[ALL LAUGHING]
How could you do this to me?
What? Discmans are retro.
Oh, is retro when you're 30
and broke
and can't afford an iPod,
schmitty?
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH]
I think "schmitty"
means loser.
We know!
You may come back in now.
I have something to say.
This better be
a good apology.
It's been a long time coming.
We have all joked around,
rolled our eyes at him.
There's been
a transgression today.
And I will no longer continue
with this group with this man.
Just skip to the "I'm sorry."
You are pathological,
and you will never change.
That is the pot
calling the kettle...
A kettle, okay?
Oh, you can say black, Pierce.
I'm a black woman.
The cat is out the bag.
You have literally identified me
as "the black woman."
Out of context.
Context is everything.
I call the other women
"flat-butt"
and "the one Abed
wants to nail."
[MOUTHING] Is that you?
[MOUTHING] Not me.
So, what's the context
for constantly referring to me
as a lesbian?
If the wallet chain fits.
Just trying to help you
find yourself.
At least he doesn't think
Shirley's my mom anymore.
He thinks we're cousins.
You're not?
Still assumes I'm a terrorist.
If you're not, I'm sorry.
And if you are, I'm a hero.
I'm willing to take that chance.
You said I have a crafty
Jew brain.
Nobody knows how to take
a compliment anymore.
Look, either he leaves
the group or I do.
[LAUGHS]
You just dug
your own grave.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, what's up?
They kicked me
out of the group!
Wanna buy some cookies?
Ten bucks a box.
Crap, damn it!
[GIRLS PANTING]
Have you seen a Chinese kid?
Twerps.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, hey, Pierce.
How is it going?
Unrepentant child.
Such a child.
Oh, here comes
stinky turd face.
Remember, we don't stop
till he's crying.
Oh, check out Franken-mom.
BRITTA:
Oh, we can use that.
No wedding ring.
He's a child of divorce.
We can make fun of him
for coming from a broken home.
I don't care if this gets dirty.
He asked for it.
You're right.
Get ready to meet
Jeff Winger, esquire.
Attorney at "Ah, snap!"
It will be better than that.
Hey, Clearasil!
What time is your mommy
picking you up?
After she's done shooting
The Real Housewives
of Greendale County?
[IMITATING JEFF]
"After she's done shooting
The Real Housewives
of Greendale County?" Duh!
That's a clever retort.
"That's a clever retort."
Duh!
Brilliant.
"Brilliant." Duh!
Your parents are divorced.
ALL:
"Your parents are divorced."
Duh!
[ALL SCOFFING]
Duh! Schmitty.
Forget it, come on.
"Come on, forget this."
Duh! Duh!
Where you going, schmitty?
KELLY:
I'm sorry, little schmitty.
Mimicry is the lowest form--
Stop talking.
"Mimicry is the lowest form..."
"Stop talking."
[♪♪♪]
Hi.
Hey, you two.
ANNIE:
What is that?
Billy,
City College's mascot.
Stealing a mascot
was part of Abed's list.
Check.
Bringing a goat
to our study group?
That's a great idea, Troy.
Thanks. Must've been
hard to say that.
It's called sarcasm, Troy.
Ask the goat
to explain it to you.
Why do I feel like
I'm being dissed?
Because you are being dissed.
Why are you two dissing Troy?
They no longer have Pierce.
What?
His social flaws
made him the scapegoat,
a lightning rod.
So there's lightning everywhere.
That sounds dangerous.
My uncle was struck
by lightning.
Think it'd give superpowers,
now he just masturbates
in theaters.
It's very dangerous.
We've lost Cliff Clavin,
our George Costanza.
Our Turtle,
or Johnny Drama, or Eve.
Man, that show is sloppy.
So, what's gonna happen?
It's only a matter of time
before one of us
becomes the new Pierce.
Well, I sure as hell am not
gonna be the new Pierce.
[WHISPERING]
And if all we need
is an escape-goat,
I think we should
just let this one go.
Sometimes,
you're pretending, Troy.
Maybe the new Pierce is Britta.
Yeah, right.
How do you pronounce bagel?
Bagel.
She calls bagels, "bagels."
We do make fun of a lot
of what you do and say.
Yeah, right to my face,
because I can take it.
Unlike a certain someone else.
[ALL GASP]
Let's not make fun of Annie.
No, no.
I don't want pity.
Come to think of it,
after him,
you're the most bigoted.
What?
You found out I was Jewish,
you called me to a "pool" party
that turned out to be
a baptism.
Excuse me for trying
to sneak you into heaven.
What about Abed?
Abed's weird.
No, that's not it.
He's all right, we like Abed.
Guys, have you considered
the new Pierce concept
is stupid?
Spoken like the new Pierce.
You're right.
I am not the new Pierce.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Damn the old Pierce.
He makes me mad.
Don't double Pierce me.
You're the triple Pierce.
Hey, guys, guys.
I can't believe
I'm gonna utter these words,
but we need Pierce
in this group.
But we can't ask Shirley
to let him back in.
That would be so insensitive.
Well, maybe he'll admit
he's wrong.
Two, three, four.
Uh, not!
We need Pierce.
ANNIE:
Just stick to the script
and make it sincere.
It's not gonna be sincere,
because I'm pretending.
You're not going back
unless she feels you're sincere.
Stubborn fool.
TROY: Can we, um, hurry this up?
Troy and I are pledging
the fraternity.
Unbeknownst to us,
we're the target of ridicule,
we won't get in.
Yeah,
they're making us walk around
with pretzels in our butts.
I put mustard on mine
like an idiot.
Okay, Pierce,
you can do this.
[♪♪♪]
What's he--?
[SIGHS]
[GASPS]
Yup.
PIERCE:
I know you don't wanna hear
what I have to say, but...
I owe you this.
From the moment
we first met,
I knew you were gonna--
Seriously!
Oh, oh, Shirley.
[CHUCKLES]
You are unbelievable!
I'm not wearing contacts.
These are mine, give them.
But I'm a bag guy.
You have the same bag,
so I thought--
That's right,
nothing is ever your fault.
Screw you.
I don't owe you an apology.
They wrote this.
Pretend like you asleep,
pretend like you asleep.
Thank you!
Now I fully understand
where I have always stood.
I'm entitled to my pride
until it gets in the way.
Got nothing to say?
Well, I do.
I'm out of the group.
Shirley.
Oh, Shirley don't go, please.
Sassy black schmitty's
out of the group.
Oh, no, not the group!
Poor, sad, little schmitties.
Can't all of us
little schmitties get along?
CHANTEL:
Would you please hurry up?
I am late for my bikini wax.
Who was that?
A punk-ass
who needs to be destroyed.
And I just figured out how.
Um, can we focus
on what's important here?
Shirley thinks we don't care.
No, no, you're right.
You're right.
That's totally more important.
I just thought of one thing.
You need to bang that kid's mom.
Um, after we fix everything
with Shirley.
Whoa!
Yes, yes, yes,
we'll deal with Shirley.
But that's brilliant!
Because then anything
he says about you...
He'll be saying to a dude
that banged his mom.
Oh, my God, you guys.
Sorry. Shirley.
Shirley.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[HORN HONKS]
All right, bye, everybody.
Have a great day.
Be right here at 3, please.
I'll be in a hurry.
[♪♪♪]
Excuse me.
Sorry to bother you.
You don't happen to have
an extra bottle of sports drink?
Actually, I do.
Here you go.
Oh, thanks.
Got to hydrate, right?
But obviously you know.
You work out.
Well, I try to keep things
where they should be.
I think I might be
where should I be.
[CHUCKLES]
[GULPS, GASPS]
TROY:
I don't know
about your robot, Abed.
Boobatron's great.
Once someone spills bong water
on his circuit, he comes alive,
gonna make us the coolest guys,
help us get babes.
Those are real babes
who will really laugh at us.
Hey, you're my friend,
right?
Friends are supposed to help
each other no matter what.
Okay,
ridiculous situation
descending
into heavy-handed drama
for the illusion of story,
check.
What? That was awesome!
All right, I am back in.
Cool. All right.
[♪♪♪]
Just so you know,
I'm Shirley.
Wouldn't want you
reaching for me
should you get a hankering
for pancakes.
PIERCE:
I'm old and I do not see well.
You already won, so shut it.
I won? Oh, no.
They want you in the group.
I quit, so you go ahead,
hang with them.
No, thanks.
I'm sick of the way
that group treats me.
Preaching to the choir.
Tell you
what I'm not gonna miss.
Abed and Troy's silly games.
Grow up already.
By the way,
thanks for including me.
Please, you think
Annie and Britta invite me
when they take those
weekend trips to the mall?
They just think of me
as some sort of mom.
They need to learn manners.
Annie needs to stop
dating Vaughn.
He's cute, but he's not the boy
I envisioned her ending up with.
No matter how hard you try,
you can never be as cool
or funny as they are.
It's called respect,
and no one ever gave me diddly.
Except me.
I respect you more
than anyone else in the group.
Which is why you pantsed me?
Well, but you see,
that wasn't wrong.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
you are such an arrogant,
self-righteous ass.
You're a strong,
dignified woman
who's raising a family.
A bigger accomplishment
than anybody else in that room.
Nobody can strip you of that,
not even me.
You really believe that?
Yes.
And that's why you think
pantsing me wasn't wrong?
It wasn't.
[CHUCKLES]
[♪♪♪]
What are you doing?
Did I misread that?
[MOANING]
CHANTEL:
Oh, here, let me just do that.
You sure
you don't want some vodka?
Oh, I'm good, I'm good.
I'm at school at 2 p.m.
Did someone just take
a schmitty?
Hey. Looks like you'll be
calling somebody daddy soon.
Or at least your mom will be.
Tonight.
[♪♪♪]
Dude, you are so pathetic.
Mark!
Mom, I've been
pwning this loser all week.
He thinks he can get back at me
through you.
What? "Powning"?
Pwning!
He doesn't even know
what that means?
I see what's going on here.
Look, I don't want to come
between a son
and his beautiful,
vivacious mom.
Oh, my God!
You are pathetic.
Yeah, so is the whore in on it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I gotta tell you, Chantel.
You have raised
a terrible human being.
We're better than this.
No, you're not!
I raised a winner
who will continue to crush
junior college losers like you.
BOY: Oh, man!
Schmitty!
I'm sorry,
it's a matter of pride.
What are you looking at?
"What are you looking at?"
Duh!
[KIDS LAUGH]
What are you looking at?
Duh. Duh!
School his ass, Mark.
"School his ass, Mark."
Duh.
"Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh!"
"Duh, duh, duh!"
"Duh, duh, duh,
duh, duh!"
ALL:
Duh. Duh, duh!
[♪♪♪]
Why are they making fun
of those handicapped kids?
They don't even realize
how much they need us.
"Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh!"
[♪♪♪]
ALL:
"Duh, duh, duh, duh!"
Why are they doing this?
I don't know if you've noticed,
but Jeff and Britta have the two
most fragile egos of the group.
Losing to these kids
will pretty much destroy them.
Hey! Whoa!
What are you, a priest?
What are you doing?
What the hell?
Hey, you didn't say, "Duh."
We win.
No.
You're the schmitties!
No, no, we're minors.
I'm calling the cops.
No, you're not.
You have already embarrassed me
by getting pwned.
Don't be such a girl, now go.
Yeah, see that.
Yes, suck it!
Schmitty face!
We showed you, high schoolers!
Suck it!
Congratulations
on your victory.
Thank you, Annie.
Yeah, thank you.
And thanks, you guys.
Any time.
Look, we are considering
rejoining the group.
And maybe we can all
be a little more mature.
TROY:
I hear that.
Abed, I've had enough
of this list.
Doing this stuff isn't fun.
It feels forced.
Fine,
I'll deactivate Boobatron.
Trust me,
classic college experiences
never happen organically.
[ALL GASP]
[LAUGHS]
Food fight!
Oh, no.
♪ I don't like studying ♪
♪ I like partying ♪
♪ I don't wanna read a book ♪
♪ Unless the subject is beer
Or boobs ♪
♪ And not pencils and books ♪
♪ The semester hasn't started ♪
♪ Until you party
Where your heart is ♪
♪ I don't wanna take a test
Unless the question is ♪
♪ Where's the party
And the answer is me ♪
♪ I drink the beer ♪
♪ I lose control ♪
♪ Why did my father
Always lie? ♪
♪ I hate science ♪
♪ Unless it helps you
Build a robot ♪
♪ Specifically
The kind programmed ♪
♪ To find another party
So I can skip chemistry ♪
♪ College is a party ♪
♪ So come party
At the party ♪
♪ Party is a class obsession ♪
♪ And the only lesson
Is to party ♪
♪ When you party with me ♪
Are you sure
it's the name of my grade school
and my favorite soft drink?
Yup, pretty sure.
George Washington Lemon Fresco.
That's a horrible porn name.
I don't make the rules.
What's yours?
Henry David Thoreau Diet Squirt.
Oh, that's good. Hello, Henry
David Thoreau Diet Squirt.
How many pornos
have you been in?
Six thousand and twelve.
How many pornos
have you been in?
Two thousand and nineteen.
That's my first week.
Impressive.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Someone here order a pizza?
Is it you guys?
It has extra sausage.
No.
It's big and hot.
That's my pizza.
But you took longer
than 30 minutes
so I'm not paying.
[PLUCKING]