[♪♪♪]
Raisins don't belong
in chocolate chip cookie.
It gives them depth.
Hey, watch it, punk.
What are you, 80?
He's the one
trying to bring back disco.
I don't have to be old
to know it's not gonna happen.
[HUMMING]
What it is, soul brother.
My boys will make me breakfast
in bed for Mother's Day.
Well, I'll make breakfast,
but they'll bring it to me.
ANNIE: Aw.
I know,
and they said
the cutest thing last night.
They said, "Mama",
'cause they call me Mama.
You're gonna be the fun police.
If I'm the fun police,
then you're director
of Funland Security.
[ALL GROANING LOUDLY]
Good, more of this.
More of what?
What do you think?
The constant bickering.
It was cute at first, but--
Well, Abed explains it best.
Jeff and Britta
is no Ross and Rachel.
Your sexual tension
and lack of chemistry
are putting us on edge,
ironically,
on every level, you're keeping
us from being friends.
Jeff and I
do not have sexual tension.
We just argue all the time.
Just like Sam and Diane.
I hated Sam and Diane.
Who are Sam and Diane?
Okay, we get it.
You're young. Sorry.
See what you're doing to us?
Want my advice?
Pork her and move on.
We did it all the time
in my day.
Yeah, you also put hydrogen
in blimps, that was bad.
PELTON:
Hey, everybody.
Just a reminder.
Our Spring Fling
is on the quad today.
Music, food, activities.
What, what?
He makes me uncomfortable.
Hmm. Still in the room.
There's also going to be a game
of Paintball Assassin
with a prize
for last man standing.
Or last man in a wheelchair
with no paint.
Or last woman.
Give it a rest, Britta. Ugh.
What's the prize?
It was a Blu-ray DVD player,
but it was stolen.
So now it's TBD.
I want TBD. Is that new?
If it's what I think,
I had it in the '70s.
Let's get back
to Britta and Jeff.
There's no Britta and Jeff.
He said, fully erect.
I'm gonna let you guys
figure this out
while I go take a nap
in my car.
What are you waiting for?
[GRUNTS]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
[PAINTBALL GUN FIRING
IN DISTANCE]
[WOMAN SCREAMS
What the hell?
[♪♪♪]
Hello?
[MAN GROANING]
What is going on?
The paintball game was starting,
and the dean--
The dean announced the prize.
The prize.
We turned on each other
like animals.
What was the prize?
Was?
This is not over.
This is still happening
right now.
[SCREAMS]
Leonard?
Leonard, I'm not playing.
Everyone's playing.
[♪♪♪]
Aw.
You suck.
Come with me if you don't want
paint on your clothes.
[THUMPING]
[ABED IMITATES CROW CAW]
Hey, look what I found
wandering the neutral zone.
Jeff Winger.
[LAUGHING]
You son of a bitch.
I thought you were dead, man.
I was just taking a nap.
Has everyone
lost their mind?
It's just
a game of paintball.
Yeah. With one rule. Last man
standing gets the prize.
The prize. The prize.
What is this prize?
[♪♪♪]
You don't know.
Priority registration.
Priority registration?
That's why everyone's running
around like a bunch--
Does that mean
what I think?
Like you could have first choice
of your classes next semester?
Easy, sugar bear.
But you could schedule
all your classes on a Monday
and take a six-day weekend.
You could do a lot of things.
Talk him through the hunger,
Abed.
Every student wants that prize,
Jeff.
There's no way to share it,
so we'll all turn on each other.
But the longer we wait
to do that-- Jeff.
The longer we work together,
the longer we last.
Is everyone running in packs?
Debate team was first,
but they fell to infighting.
Glee club is luring stragglers
into sniper traps
with cheery renditions
of hit songs.
Really?
And people fall for that?
Yeah.
I mean, I'm all for winning,
but let's not resort
to cheap ploys.
Are the girls in the game?
You mean Britta?
I don't mean Britta.
Did I say Britta?
Twice now.
Chess Club.
No, no, no.
He's a pawn.
[♪♪♪]
Checkmate, bitches.
And tell the drama club
their tears will be real today.
STAR-BURNS:
No, that's all sugar.
Get some protein.
PIERCE: Right here. Peanuts.
STAR-BURNS: Yeah, yeah. Peanuts.
Take the stuff closer to you.
No, no.
The ones in the back
are the freshest.
STAR-BURNS:
That will keep us going.
Yeah. Okay, okay.
Hey.
What the hell?
I got you covered.
You guys formed an alliance
without me?
Yeah. You with Star-Burns?
Well,
not if I can be with you.
[YELLS]
It's just Star-Burns.
Anyone else
need a pee break?
Yeah.
Hey.
I'll stand guard.
I don't need to pee.
I'm wearing a diaper
for the game.
JEFF:
Oh, yeah. For the game.
Hey, guys, make this quick
before Pierce's chewing
attracts enemies.
[♪♪♪]
Um, guys?
Hold it.
Don't move.
TROY: Drop it.
[ALL YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
[♪♪♪]
All right, everybody, be cool.
We can beat the others
if we merge.
We're doing fine.
You gonna win camped on crapper?
Worked on you.
Did it?
You have a gun in your face.
Matches yours.
Nice comeback.
ALL:
Shut up!
BOTH:
Jeez.
Okay.
So the agreement is we're allies
until we're sure
we're the last seven standing.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
Mm-hm.
Our team's walking
with God.
I'm thinking we might already
be the only seven left,
in which case,
this is a window
for the two of us
to take out the others.
Real nice, that'd be great PR
for the black students.
I am not an ambassador.
I am gladiator.
Now, you want to win or not?
Oh!
Troy made God mad.
Take cover.
[♪♪♪]
SHIRLEY:
Run, Pierce.
[PEOPLE SINGING
IN DISTANCE]
Glee club.
How do you know?
Listen.
[SINGERS HARMONIZING]
SINGERS:
♪ Hit me with your best shot ♪
Oh, brother.
That is so uninspired.
I'm not so sure.
I got a plan.
Get ready.
Hey, Pierce.
Don't come over here, okay?
Screw you.
I'm coming over there.
[GRUNTING]
Medic.
In the trees. There.
[GROANING]
Write some original songs!
SHIRLEY:
What are you guys gonna do
if you win
priority registration?
I'll make my schedule airtight.
Maybe get out of here
in three years instead of four.
I'd take any class with no tests
and no papers.
What would you do,
Shirley?
SHIRLEY:
I'd choose all morning classes
so I could get home early
to spend some time with my boys.
It's hard being away
from them so much.
You know what?
I say if any of us win,
we give it to Shirley
as a Mother's Day gift.
Absolutely.
JEFF: What?
Abed,
you don't have to do that.
I am so sick of you
guilting people
with your phony
humanitarian shtick.
Phony? When I win,
you can watch me do it.
Of course, but that won't
make it less phony.
You'd be
a lot more likeable--
If I never did anything
for anybody?
Yeah, because when you help,
that always turns out great.
Let's do it.
[SQUEAKING]
Shh.
MAN [IN SING-SONG VOICE]:
Study group. Come out and play.
Oh, look,
it's post-ironic Disco Stu.
Still trying to bring it back?
Hi.
[SKATERS LAUGHING]
Damn, he brought it back.
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
Put your hands--
The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
[GUN CLICKS]
MAN 2:
They shot us.
MAN 3:
It's hot, it's hot.
Let's go, fool.
[PAINTBALL GUN FIRING
AND PEOPLE SCREAMING]
The last guy almost got me.
[♪♪♪]
My legs.
Oh, Shirley, I'm so sorry.
I'm going home, Britta.
I know, Shirley, I know.
No, seriously, I'm going home.
Can you help me up?
Oh. Yeah, sure.
[GRUNTS]
Shirley, I'm gonna win
for you and your boys.
That's nice.
I'm gonna win that prize,
but not for you and your boys.
SHIRLEY:
That's less nice.
Oh, my God, you've been hit.
What?
Oh, no.
Wait, wait.
It's blood.
I thought it was paint,
but I'm just bleeding.
Talk about luck.
I can't believe this game
is still going on. It's 2 a.m.
What if someone gets hurt
and the police come?
They'll think I'm a bad dean.
There's classes in the morning.
This has to stop.
Shh.
Put me in the game,
because I'll take everyone out.
I play paintball
three times a week, bro.
I'm one of the douches
who brings his own equipment.
But it wouldn't be fair.
You're not a student.
But you can change that,
can't you? Huh?
Enroll me in a class.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
What are your interests?
Arts and crafts.
Oh, I do watercolors.
Oh, cool.
[♪♪♪]
[BRITTA LAUGHS]
The group would be thrilled.
The wounded soldier fantasy
means we're moments
from doing it, right?
JEFF:
Yeah, can you feel that tension?
It's a miracle
we still have clothes on.
You're right, you know.
I am a phony.
I try to act compassionate,
because I'm afraid that I'm not.
Oh, please, I invented phony.
You care about people.
I accuse you of faking
to convince myself
I'm not such a jerk.
You help people more than I do,
and you don't even want to.
You're not a jerk.
You're fine.
Especially now
that I've repaired
your overworked torso
with my trembling fingers.
Yes.
Too much sexual tension.
Damn bursting.
[BOTH BABBLING]
It would totally
serve them right
if we did it here
in the study room.
God, could you imagine?
I can't stop imagining.
Neither can I.
[BOTH BABBLING]
We should get dressed
before the third-shift librarian
shows up.
We don't want this to turn
into a letter to Penthouse.
I think the group is right.
We did need
to relieve some tension.
[♪♪♪]
Tell me you didn't have sex
with me to win at paintball.
No, I had sex with you, and
now I'm gonna win at paintball.
Don't be gross.
I'm gross?
You seem pretty practiced
at putting on panties one-handed
while holding a gun.
Can I get dressed
before you assassinate me?
So all that happened,
it meant nothing to you?
I didn't say that.
What did it mean to you?
I asked you first.
Very mature.
Said the woman
wearing Hello Kitty underwear.
Said the woman holding
the gun.
You sure that's a gun?
Maybe it's a metaphor
for your fake, jaded persona.
[GUN CLICKS]
Uh-oh.
No paintballs, Hans?
You think I'm stupid?
When'd you take it?
When you started seducing me.
I wasn't though.
Assuming that
makes you grosser.
Not when I'm right.
[♪♪♪]
Buenos dias, children.
You'll be happy to know
you made it till the end.
You're not a student.
CHANG: Wrong.
Critical Media Literacy
and Politics of Gender, biatch.
Give me your clip.
That would be brilliant of me.
Look, you got the drop on me.
I lost.
Let me do this for you.
Be pretty crazy
if I shot you right now, huh?
[♪♪♪]
[CHANG CACKLING]
What's so funny, Chang?
Maybe it's the fact
there's no such thing
as priority registration.
Or maybe it's this.
Ta-da.
[CHANG LAUGHING]
[BEEPING]
[♪♪♪]
[CACKLING]
JEFF:
Dean!
Just one moment.
Oh, hi there, Jeffrey.
That's a good look for you.
Everybody out there is shooting
each other for nothing
while you sit here
in your ivory tower.
Jeffrey, I can explain.
I messed up when I promised
priority registration.
It's a violation
of some student equality act,
but this isn't. Ta-da!
Okay, now, it's not Blu-ray,
but it comes
with its own remote, so...
[♪♪♪]
Jeffrey.
[SCREAMING]
PELTON:
Jeffrey!
Jeffrey. Jeffrey!
You get it all out
of your system?
[LAUGHING]
Almost.
What do you want from me?
Guess.
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
Oh, hi.
Hey, how's it going?
You still
have some paint.
Oh, thanks.
Um, I was thinking--
You don't have to.
It didn't happen.
It's not a mistake.
Just that it didn't happen.
It was a crazy night
of paintball.
Exactly. Tension relieving.
Absolutely. No need
to mention it to anyone.
Right, no big deal.
Nothing's changed.
Something's changed.
Oh, Abed. Crazy Abed.
No, something's different now.
Me? I'm sporting a man-thong.
Maybe.
Or maybe it's that I
have emerged victorious
with a priority registration
form.
Oh!
Well done, Jeff.
And in recognition
of her bravery,
not to mention her children,
I hereby award this
to the best soldier, Shirley.
Now, the bad news is,
for legal purposes,
next semester,
if anybody asks, you have gout.
Do you mind walking with a limp?
Mm.
Thank you, Jeffrey.
Look, Annie.
Wow, I didn't see that coming.
Neither did I.
So no one feels it?
No one senses anything's
different?
Nope.
Not at all.
It's riding up a little.
[♪♪♪]
TROY:
Hey, Abed, it's Troy.
Meet you at the flagpole in--
WOMAN [ON RECORDING]:
If you are satisfied
with your message, press one.
To erase and re-record--
Hey, Abed, it's Troy.
Yo, I'll meet you
at the flagpole in like--
If you are satisfied
with your message--
[IN HIGH VOICE]
Hey, Abed. It's Troy.
Hee-hee!
If you are satisfied
with your message--
When are you gonna meet him?
[NORMAL VOICE]: Ten minutes.
To listen to your message--
Your girlfriend will meet you
at the flagpole in 10 minutes.
Goodbye.
If you are satisfied
with your message, press one.
To erase and re-record...
Did I sound like a jerk?
To listen to your message,
press three. To send--
[PHONE BEEPS]
Hey, Abed,
sorry to bother you.
Troy will meet you
at the flagpole in 10 minutes.
Okay.
If you are satisfied...
Maybe just send a text message.
Yeah.