PELTON [OVER PA]:
It's hard to believe
finals are here.
And I know
during this stressful time,
my voice blaring over a PA
can't help.
Which is why,
for the next three days,
you'll hear nothing
but soothing sounds of nature.
And to kick it off,
here's a babbling brook.
[WATER BURBLING
ON RECORDING OVER PA]
Will anyone back me up
if I say this is ridiculous,
or is it gonna be
another Avatar situation?
I love Avatar.
Okay!
We're not gonna have trouble
passing our final.
I've transcribed notes
from my digital recorder.
You record every class?
Spoiler alert.
You mean, nerd alert.
Alert nerd.
Here's a spoiler.
We're gonna spend
the next three days boning up.
Then pass the exam
and move on to Spanish 103.
Sounds like a good ending,
Annie.
Except for where I take
Spanish 103.
What do you mean?
Spanish 102 fills
my language requirement.
I guess I just figured
we're a Spanish study group,
so we'd keep taking Spanish
together.
That's what I thought too.
I'm in.
I'm on a tight,
four-year schedule
to replace my bachelor's.
I'm not gonna take
an extra class.
Spanish has value beyond credit.
JEFF: Not really.
I know the family
downstairs hates me.
I don't need
to understand why.
Okay, fine. You want me
to say it? I'll say it.
I like this group.
I want it to stay together.
[GROUP CHATTERING]
ANNIE:
Yeah, you be the cool guy,
Jeff.
And next fall
when that gets lonely,
I'll be in the front row
of Spanish 103.
[GROUP CHATTERING]
Monday through Friday,
6:00 a.m.
Six--
[PA CLICKS ON]
PELTON [OVER PA]:
And now, crickets.
[CRICKETS CHIRPING
ON RECORDING OVER PA]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Okay, if we're not interested
in Spanish 103 next year,
what about Anthropology?
Ooh. Anthropology.
The study of man.
I'm still trying to forget what
I learned about that subject.
Go, girl.
You just go-girled yourself.
Shut up.
ANNIE:
See, it's fun.
And they have a class at noon.
Noon, everybody.
Anthropology? Anthropology?
Anthropology?
Annie, I'm not big
on planning ahead,
but I have one
unmovable appointment,
May 23rd, 2013.
To buy a flying car?
I have a table
at Morty's Steakhouse
where I'll celebrate
becoming a lawyer again,
which can only happen
if I take a full load.
Don't.
A full load of classes
every year.
I can maybe make it
until then,
but not by building my schedule
around BFFs.
We'll build ours
around yours.
You realize
we'll be friends
whether or not
we have a class together?
Of course you think that,
Britta.
It's obvious from your name
your parents smoked pot.
I haven't said a single word
in this entire conversation
and I find that outrageous.
Hola, el losers.
Winger, may I have a word
with you in private?
Sure.
Good.
SHIRLEY: Sorry.
Oh, yeah.
Got it. Cool.
CHANG:
Come back in 10 minutes.
And if anyone asks,
I sent you to learn things.
And, Pierce,
close the door, please.
Gracias.
Other side of the door.
[♪♪♪]
So you're here
because your college degree
was fake, right?
I prefer the term better
than real, but yes.
Two questions:
Where did you get it?
Could you have prevented
being caught, and how?
One question:
Where did you learn
to count questions?
Are you telling me
you need a fake degree?
You know, in high school,
I was in a band.
We could've been huge,
but the world wasn't ready
for an Asian man
on keytar.
Did you say "keytar"
or did you pronounce "guitar"
like a hillbilly?
Keytar. It's a keyboard
you can play like a guitar.
Oh.
Get with the times, man.
Anyway,
next thing you know, I'm 32.
And I'm bagging groceries
for, like, 5 bucks an hour
plus tips.
Shocked?
Confused.
I'm supposed to tip
my bag boy?
So I did what anyone
would do.
I faked my way
into a job
as a Spanish teacher
at a community college,
relying on phrases
from Sesame Street.
Oh, my God.
Save the judgment, Winger,
all right?
If the dean finds out
that I'm not a real teacher,
your grades are invalid,
and you'll all have to repeat
this class.
[CHAIR CREAKS]
That was the chair.
Good.
[IMITATES JEFF]
[♪♪♪]
[MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY]
It's unsolvable.
[♪♪♪]
Hold on. I forgot my--
Hey. What the hell
are you doing?
Hey.
Hey, come back here!
Come back here!
Jerry. Hey, Jerry.
Check this out.
[♪♪♪]
MAN [ON RECORDING]:
And that is what Milton
was really saying.
Okay, exams are on Tuesday.
Class dismissed.
CHANG [ON HEADPHONES]:
If the dean finds out
that I'm not a real teacher,
your grades are invalid
and you'll all have
to repeat this class.
If the dean finds out
that I'm not a real teacher,
your grades are invalid,
and you'll all have to repeat
this class.
[CHAIR CREAKS ON RECORDING]
That was the chair.
Right.
[♪♪♪]
Hi, everybody. Hi.
I'm afraid I have some
bad news for you, kids.
Well, it's actually bad news
for the older people as well.
Señor Chang
is no longer with us.
Um. He's not faking
his death again, is he?
Because I can't handle that.
First, he's alive.
Then we're happy.
And then he's alive again and--
I received an anonymous tip
that Chang
had misrepresented
certain aspects
of his qualifications.
For instance, having them.
Word of advice.
If an Asian man
says he's a Spanish teacher,
it's not racist
to ask for proof, okay?
You ignore your mother's voice,
get into that horse's mouth.
So if Chang's a fraud,
what about our grades?
Are they invalid?
Oh, no, no, no.
That's not fair to you guys.
I'm sure you've all worked
very hard and learned.
So just take your final
with Chang's replacement.
Doctor.
[♪♪♪]
Buenos días.
ALL: Buenos días.
[IN SPANISH]
ALL:
Sí.
Buenos días.
ALL:
Sí.
Listen to this
back and forth.
It's like I'm at an embassy.
What's on the final?
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
I know it's in Spanish,
dummy.
What chapters?
All three or...?
Veinte.
Oh, I know that one.
She wants a large coffee.
Oh. She's thinking.
[IN ENGLISH]
Okay, in English.
You will be taking a standard
exam for students at your level.
It will cover
this entire textbook.
[♪♪♪]
El crappo.
I couldn't understand
a word Dr. Escodera was saying.
And why is she teaching Spanish
if she's a doctor?
Go cure something.
[CAR ALARM BLARING]
I gotta pass that exam
or my entire four-year plan
will be thrown off.
That might be your car,
Jeff.
What?
I was on my roof
for the 4th of July,
the fireworks set off
the car alarms.
That one sounded
like a brand-new Lexus.
My Lexus isn't brand-new.
I know.
Yours is a 2002.
That's the year I heard it.
[YELLING]
Hey!
You two-faced jag.
You're wearing protective
goggles to destroy my car?
Safety first.
Stop!
I ask you for help
and you turn me in?
What? I did not.
Why would I screw myself?
What am I, Dr. Drew?
I didn't do it, okay?
[KEYTAR PLAYS]
Tell me who did it
so I can murder your face.
GUARD:
Hey, break it up.
Oh. Oh, oh.
We're writing a song.
For the battle of bands.
[BOTH SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
[YELLS]
Good luck passing your exam,
Winger.
At one point,
I was teaching you Klingon.
Why don't you tell that
to your weird-sounding chair.
I have a condition.
[GRUNTING]
I'm peeing. I'm peeing.
I'm peeing.
[♪♪♪]
[WHISTLING]
Impressive.
I dismantled that valve
and I put out that free cake
because I wanted to see
what you could do.
You got a gift, kid.
You know that, right?
A gift for sinks.
Big deal.
I'm a student.
I like learning.
Yeah, right. Learning.
Learn everything.
Learn until you're dead.
Or...
you can call this number.
That's a company
that fixes toilets and sinks.
Oh, man.
Listen to me.
Toilets and sinks,
real things.
Things that people always use
and always need to get fixed.
This is a life, kid.
A real one.
Doing something that matters,
that makes sense.
The only thing
that makes sense is this.
Learning, thoughts.
So I can think,
and get a student loan,
and grind my own coffee,
and understand HBO.
You don't have to do that, kid.
You're special.
You could be a plumber.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
Hey.
Hi.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, so we know
three kinds of verbs,
which took 40 minutes.
At this rate,
if we don't sleep or pee,
we can cover
10 percent of the exam.
If it's multiple choice,
25 percent of our guesses
will be right.
That's a lot
of right answers
when you're guessing
everything.
I don't wanna sound
like a defeatist,
but we're defeated.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Face it.
Why even take the exam?
We're all gonna be
retaking Spanish this fall.
[SHIRLEY GROANS
AND ANNIE SIGHS]
What was that?
What was what?
I don't know.
I said retake Spanish
and everyone went, "Ugh."
And you went, "Hmm."
Maybe it's one of those
recessive genes.
I can also curl my tongue.
Who else?
[ALL LAUGH]
Annie ratted out Chang.
What?
You made this happen
because you're obsessed
with all of us being together.
I wouldn't say
I was obsessed.
Permission to treat
the witness as hostile?
I'll allow it.
Did you record
yesterday's Spanish class?
I don't think so.
Abed?
You said you record
all your classes.
Pierce called it
a spoiler alert.
You heard Chang tell me
he was bogus.
And then dropped the dime
because you would do anything
to keep this group together.
Because you are insecure.
Because you didn't get hot
until after high school.
That's true.
Fine. I did it.
For real, Annie?
Oh, Annie.
Someone make her a dude
so I can punch her.
Go ahead and hate me.
It's better.
We were all gonna
drift apart.
You were all too cool
to do anything.
Maybe not too cool, maybe just,
you know, not psycho enough.
A little crazy.
Little psycho.
Now she is going to make
the Disney face.
Her lip is gonna quiver
her eyes will flutter,
but they won't ever
actually close.
But do not feel
sorry for her.
She stole a year of our lives,
and we're right to be pissed.
Oh, Annie.
No. No.
Everyone close their eyes.
Do it. Close them.
Abed, close.
Oh, don't worry about me.
I can only connect
with people through--
movies.
She's the Ark of the Covenant.
[GASPS]
You guys, I'm sorry.
I only did it
so that we could stay friends.
Picture her as Paul Giamatti.
[ALL GROAN]
I mean, he's--
Friends don't do
what you did to us.
Did the sisterhood
of the traveling pants
poison each other's food
so they were too sick to leave?
No.
I've never seen it,
but I'm pretty sure
they mailed each other pants.
I said I was sorry.
Who cares if you're sorry?
We're still screwed.
Be sorry about this stuff
before you do it.
Then don't do it.
It's called growing up.
We were gonna see each other
all the time.
Yeah, that's what
my rehab group used to say.
The only one
that keeps in touch
is the guy that sells jewelry
made out of bottle caps.
I had hoped
that this group would amount
to more
than passing hellos
and whatever the hell this is.
[ANNIE CRYING]
Nobody even think
about going after her.
That's what she wants,
more personal drama
so we fail the exam
and stay in Spanish forever.
We have to beat her.
Don't text her. Don't call her.
Don't mention her.
We do not need her to study.
[♪♪♪]
Does anybody know
how to study?
Annie usually--
Whose side are you on?
[♪♪♪]
[ANIMAL GRUNTING
ON RECORDING OVER PA]
PELTON [OVER PA]:
Happy finals week, Greendale.
Continuing our stress-reducing
nature sounds,
that's cut five
from Sounds of the Serengeti.
Here's a B-side
from that album,
"Antelope Slaughter at Ndutu."
[LION ROARS &amp; ANTELOPE
SHRIEKS ON RECORDING OVER PA]
Oh, God.
Did we miss the exam?
No, it starts
in 40 minutes.
Uh, I can't wake up Pierce.
Is this gonna take
an unexpected turn?
You have to know
how to do it.
Discrimination lawsuit.
Preposterous.
Should we call Annie?
Absolutely not.
Keep your eyes on the prize
and let her grow up.
I'll see you all at the exam.
Wait for me, Britta.
I was with you
in the bathroom yesterday.
You're with me everywhere.
I know
you could be a plumber.
I'm not gonna be, okay?
I'm gonna be sophisticated
and have no job,
or a job
that looks from a distance
like I do nothing.
Troy, you know what the best
part of my day is?
Ten seconds from the time
I sit down in Spanish
to the time
I look at your desk.
Because I think maybe I'll look
and he won't be there.
[♪♪♪]
Between our studying
for 12 hours,
and Pierce being asleep
for 11 of them,
I think we may actually
stand a chance.
My horoscope
predicted suffering.
No, no, that's good.
Horoscopes are the devil
trying to trick us.
Mm-hmm.
Oh.
[♪♪♪]
Yeah.
That make you happy?
Why aren't you at your desk?
I don't wanna sit near you
because you're a bad friend.
He said
the best part of his day
is when he thinks
I won't be there.
Abed,
what a terrible thing to say.
It's from a movie.
Then the movie it's from
is terrible.
[IN SPANISH]
Where's Annie?
Oh, I sent her a text.
She hasn't responded yet.
Shirley,
what did I tell you?
Don't play into her ploy.
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
What does it say?
She says she's fine
and this isn't a ploy
for attention.
She's sorry.
She does need to grow up,
starting by making things right
with Chang.
Oh, no.
What?
He'll kill her.
[IN SPANISH]
[IN ENGLISH]
Who cares about a stupid exam?
We're a study group.
And Annie's our friend.
[IN SPANISH]
[CLEARS THROAT]
I'm friends with Hannah too.
The whole class is.
And you can't have an exam
without a class.
Right, guys?
We love Hannah!
ALL [CHANTING]:
ANNIE:
No!
Oh, no.
The devil told the truth.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
CHANG:
Whoa.
Winger, what the hell?
What was that screaming?
I was showing Annie
the magic
of electronic sampling.
[ANNIE'S SCREAM PLAYING
ON RECORDING]
We thought
you were murdering her.
Annie getting me fired
was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
She's helping me
re-plan my life.
She's got a real mind
for stuff like this.
We're gonna find Ben a job
so he can stay as a student
and work on
his teaching degree.
And music classes, you know?
Maybe get the band
back together, huh?
[KEYTAR PLAYING]
Oh. Listen to that.
Yeah. Music lessons
would be great for you.
Oh, thanks, Britta.
Now go pass that test.
[CHUCKLES]
[♪♪♪]
Well, it was kind of easy,
right?
I think I might have passed.
Jeff, I can never forgive myself
for what I did.
Look, I treated you like
a child for having feelings.
Maybe because that's,
you know,
when I stopped having them.
But you shouldn't.
You don't have to be a kid
to admit that you like people.
And you don't have to dress
like this to grow up.
You look like a travel agent.
You don't like it?
I was going
for more of a professor thing.
What? Why?
What?
Nothing.
I got half of it, which got me
through the half I didn't.
Like the first season
of The Wire.
Exactly-- Ah, hell,
I can't stay mad at you.
I think I nailed it.
Oh, me too.
I'm feeling pretty confident.
I think we're gonna make it.
Still, we should plan
for the worst-case scenario.
Because if we do all pass,
that means next year,
we won't have a class together.
So we're gonna need a backup.
Anthropology? Anthropology?
Anthropology?
[ALL CHUCKLE]
Anthropology.
ABED:
I want you to be
in my next film.
Barnes, Troy: 68.
Bennett, Shirley: 81.
Oh!
Edison, Annie: 95.
Hawthorne, Pierce: 70.
Nadir, Abed: 85.
Perry, Britta: 79.
Winger, Jeff--
I'm sorry, Jeff.
I'm sorry for the half-hearted
mislead, 80.
We all pass Spanish.
[ALL CHEER]
Not to take anything away
from anyone,
but didn't the test seem
extra easy?
I don't know.
Uh-uh.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, thanks.
For making it easy.
I was going to say
the same to you,
but you were gone
before breakfast.
I'm an early riser.
I'll say.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]