[♪♪♪]
Thanks for a great year.
You got it.
Mr. Winger. I hope you will be
seizing the day this summer.
Thanks, Professor Whitman.
And I hope you'll be seizing
a more contemporary movie.
Looking good, Leonard.
Stroke or tai chi?
Tai chi.
Keep it up.
And keep up whatever it is
you're doing, Garrett.
It's called chillaxing.
Duh.
Hey-hey, what's up, Jeff?
Hi.
Hello, good morning, howdy.
[LAUGHS]
Wait, Jeff.
I'll walk with you.
I'll see you.
Okay.
Uh, I got class in,
like, five hours, so...
All right,
I'll see you, babe. Sayonara.
Can't believe I made it through
my first year of college.
I finally get to click
"send"
on so many
I-told-you-so e-mails.
Yeah, it's pretty great.
Not much could ruin today.
Hi.
Oh, shoot.
I forgot saying that
summons him.
Will you two be attending
tomorrow's transfer ceremony
to send off
all the students
leaving for so-called
real schools?
There's a formal dance
afterward.
How many dances
is this school gonna have?
Five.
If you come to all of them,
you get one of these.
I assumed your whole posse
would be coming,
having heard the exciting news
about Britta.
Banana rhino.
[ALL LAUGH]
Banana Sam Elliott.
[TROY CHUCKLES]
LeVar Banana Burton.
[CHUCKLES]
Banana King Tut.
Here, give me that.
It's more like this.
[CHUCKLES]
Banana penis.
[PIERCE LAUGHS]
Sure you would've loved it
if he did it.
What?
What's happened to you and me,
Troy?
Remember how hard we laughed
when we first heard the term
"teacher's aids?"
Yeah.
And then we found out
a teacher did have AIDS.
So, what's everybody
doing this summer?
I'm taking the boys on a trip.
I hope I can convince them
for one more year
that motels
are tiny little theme parks.
Yeah, I got to find
a new place to live.
My dad wants me
to leave the nest
so he feels less weird
that his girlfriend is 20.
You could live in a pyramid.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, wait.
Abed. Your dorm room's
got a bunk bed, right?
Yep.
Um, everyone has to go
to the transfer dance tomorrow.
I'm going.
My friend Gary's transferring.
Oh, good!
Finally.
I hope he transfers to hell.
JEFF:
More importantly,
our very own Britta Perry,
it turns out, has been nominated
for transfer queen.
Oh, that's nice.
What the hell
is a transfer queen?
It's like prom queen. You wear
a sash, there's a vote.
If you win,
they put a crown on your head.
And I am so jealous,
I want to murder you.
Aren't you excited?
No.
How did I get nominated?
Don't let it upset you, Britta.
It's the last day of semester.
Nothing can ruin that.
Hi!
Amazing.
He's like an evil genie.
Just spreading the news.
Some folks say
"transfer formal"
isn't really rolling
off the tongue,
so we're just gonna call it
the tranny dance.
Much more Greendale.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
What kind of community college
has a prom?
Proms weren't cool
in high school.
It's that kind of crap
that made me drop out.
You know, you don't actually
have to lie on a sofa
like it's a Woody Allen movie.
Thank you for telling me that
in the last session.
Now, look, there are bugs
on the windshield of your mind,
you may never be able
to squeegee,
like a certain birthday party
attended by a rather
enterprising transient
in a dinosaur costume.
But there are other more
recent streaks
that you might yet be able
to wipe clear,
like your adolescent fear
of being a so-called
blow-up doll.
I really think this nomination
may actually help that.
You think
I'd feel better about myself
if I got all sexed up,
went over there,
and really tried to be crowned
queen of the dingbats?
Precisely.
Wow.
You really get what you pay for
with free therapy.
Ouch. That stung a little bit.
Thanks.
BOTH:
Ugh.
I'll save you time.
He listens to you talk,
then recommends a makeover.
Don't wear as much lipstick
as you did on Valentine's Day.
Your mouth looked
like a coin purse.
Señor Chang,
Greendale's foremost,
if only, Spanish teacher.
What can I do for you?
I am actually a student now.
But I was thinking,
as a teacher, and as my friend,
um, if you could help me...
cheat my way through school.
I have a counterproposal.
How about
I point out to you
we've never actually
been friends,
then laugh at your
very well-deserved misfortune?
[♪♪♪]
Let's just try that a second.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[LAUGHS]
No, Jorge, you killed it.
Are you going to Abed's kegger?
JORGE:
Heck, yeah. You know it, jefe.
You probably don't
wanna talk to me.
It's not junior high.
We're mature adults, Michelle.
We can talk.
I think I handled
our breakup poorly.
Before I respond to that,
I'll have to take
an extra-strength vitamin duh.
Duh.
We started getting serious
and I got scared.
It's possible
I made a mistake.
Maybe we can talk about it
sometime.
I miss you.
Mm-mm.
Why don't you take a picture?
It'll last longer.
Cool.
[RAP MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Dope kegger.
Thanks.
It's funny.
You know,
I spend so much time here,
I forget
that we don't live together.
Then I think,
"What if we lived together?"
I'm gonna check
on the other keg.
Have you ever seen one of these?
It's called a beer bong.
You're not supposed
to inhale though.
I almost died outside.
Why does Abed hate me?
What, are you kidding?
He probably hates America.
Hey, babe.
Baby, guess what.
Your boyfriend
just got offered a spot
on the number one
Hacky Sack team in the nation.
Oh, my God, sweetie.
I'm assuming that's huge.
Of course it's huge.
I mean, you know.
I'm not into fame and stuff,
but I could be the next
Vngwe Mackadangdang, Jr.
I know.
There's one thing,
mountain flower,
that's that the, uh,
school's in Delaware.
Thank you.
You know, if you don't go
to this dance tomorrow,
we're not gonna see
each other for months.
It's not a Jane Austen novel.
We have cell phones.
What? Ah-- Oh.
Oh, jeez, sorry.
What are you doing?
You had hair
I was gonna move.
You were gonna move
my hair?
I don't know.
Have you ever thought of
yourself as a guarded person?
Am I? Watch.
Ow.
See? It's alarming, right?
Right?
Oh. Oh, Professor Slater, hi.
What are you doing here?
Oh, you know, end of the year,
randomly wandering.
Hi, Jeff.
Are you two...?
BOTH:
No.
The two of you aren't...?
BOTH: No.
No, just friends.
Same here.
Good, for you.
Will I see you at the dance,
Britta?
Kind of obligated,
seeing as I'm nominated
for queen, so...
Oh. I thought you were
all into female empowerment.
What's more empowering
than a woman in a crown?
[BOTH LAUGH]
Just did my first keg stand.
Ha-ha!
Can't feel my legs.
[GRUNTS]
♪ Dancing in your underwear ♪
♪ Taking air conditioner
Repair ♪
♪ So you can get a job ♪
♪ Greendale's the way it goes ♪
Whoo!
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
Our original school song
by the venerable
Pierce Hawthorne.
He made that up. Hmm?
Everyone remember
to vote before the coronation.
The nominees
are identified with sashes
that say, "tranny queen."
By the way,
we do offer summer classes,
which are a great way to, um--
Um-- Broaden your mind.
Have fun.
Hi. You're here for me.
Guys. Guys.
Vaughn got recruited
to a college in Delaware.
I'm gonna go with him
for the summer.
A classic last-day-of-school
plot twist.
He's gonna be the next
Vngwe Mackadangdang, Jr.
It's a Hacky Sack guy.
Hey, you don't
have to tell us who
Ingmar Mackadingdong, Jr. is.
Hmm.
Jeff, help me
with some refreshments.
Please don't tell anyone
until after I'm gone.
I'm not just going to Delaware
for the summer.
I'm transferring with Vaughn.
What?
When did you decide that?
I spent three months
researching backpacks
before I chose the one
that I use now.
I don't want to be that person
anymore.
I want to live in the moment.
For your and Vaughn's sake,
I hope it works out.
But on behalf
of the rest of the group,
I hope it's a catastrophe.
You better visit.
Whoa. I can't believe
nobody's taken this cookie.
Señor Chang,
is there a word in Spanish
for someone who used to pretend
to be a professor
but was a teacher,
but wasn't actually a teacher,
and is now a student?
Is there a word for that?
Oh.
If it was in Spanish,
you wouldn't know.
Bup-bup-bup.
Hit a professor,
you'll get expelled.
I will find a loophole.
Oh.
Good luck with that.
Then I'll kill you.
Dudley Moore.
Spray tan.
I'd go easy on that punch
if I was you.
I've put in a little--
Hot person, hot people.
The two of them coming this way.
Which one do you want?
Hi, Jeff.
Oh!
Oh.
Britta, you look great.
Such a stunning improvement.
Wow, you look gorgeous.
It must've taken all day.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, Jeff, you've got a...
Oh.
It's right there.
[BOTH MUMBLING]
Guys, guys,
cleanest face ever.
Hey, am I okay?
Yes.
Yeah.
You know, Troy,
uh, our study group,
after all we've been through,
we got to stick together.
You, me, and Jeff
and Rain Man,
and big boobs and medium boobs
and black boobs.
We're a family.
What's your point?
I'd like to make an offer.
Okay.
Am I black boobs?
Last call.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
Study over.
What are you doing?
Giving things a finale vibe.
Well, how's this
for a finale vibe?
Pierce asked me
to move in with him,
in his mansion.
More of a spin-off vibe,
but you should do it.
I thought we were friends.
We are.
That's why we shouldn't be
roommates. We'll end up fighting
and putting a masking tape line
down the middle of our room.
We just
won't get masking tape.
You should live
with someone who you like
but whose friendship
wouldn't be altered
because of constant irritation,
that's Pierce.
If you and I move in,
we jump the shark.
That will end it.
Maybe you're ending it.
Oh, and for the record,
there was an episode
of Happy Days
where a guy
literally jumped over a shark.
And it was the best one.
[♪♪♪]
I think I'm winning.
Winning tranny queen.
Yeah.
So, uh, isn't it nice
that Jeff and Slater
are getting back together?
What?
Aha. And psych!
But they will
get back together
if you don't stop
competing with her
and start communicating
with Jeff.
She already has a head start.
They slept together.
Holy macaroni with pepper jack.
When? Where?
During paintball
in the study room
with Colonel Mustard.
Does it matter?
Now it does matter.
Where in the study room?
On the couches.
We use those.
Oh, get over it.
I've seen you shake
the dean's hand.
Who knows where he's been?
Do you believe in soul mates?
Uh-huh.
Um, okay.
Now, don't be mad at me.
I didn't think more than
one person would answer the ad.
Yes, dream coming true.
You guys are leaving already?
Yeah. Got to be in Delaware
by tomorrow night.
Hey.
I'll see you soon.
[BOTH MUMBLING]
Have a good summer.
I'll see you in the fall, Annie.
Mm.
[CHUCKLES]
We're gonna miss you.
You're the one
that didn't want me
in the study group.
Come on, that's not true.
Yeah, none of us did.
I say things others won't.
That has value.
Well, bye.
See you. Lates.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Good evening, Michelle.
Or may I say, Meow-chelle?
Who has your car keys?
They're in the taco meat.
Now, what say you and I
blow this pop stand,
and head off
for a spot of slap and tickle?
[WHISPERING]
I mean sex,
in case the lingo
hasn't made it to the States.
I think I'm probably
leaving here with Jeff.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I'm sorry.
I just assumed
you two were done,
since, uh, ahem,
Jeff and Britta did, uh,
the yankee doodle.
Don't tell me that
didn't make it to the States.
It clearly originated here.
Okay, we finished
tallying all 36 votes,
so everyone get ready.
Yo, Goldilocks.
Drop the smirk.
I know about
your grungy tumble,
and I'm sure it was
the highlight of your diary
but it was during a pit stop
in something real.
You were the pit stop.
He used you to numb the pain
of not getting with me.
Jeff needs a girl who doesn't
just not wear underwear
because Oprah told her
it would spice things up.
He needs a girl
who doesn't wear underwear
because she hasn't done laundry
in three weeks.
He's been to flavor
country now.
They should retire the table
we did it on.
Table?
Miss Britta Perry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have to go.
I just won a contest
for being hot.
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
Oh, wow.
This is a huge honor.
This may come
as a surprise to you,
but I've never actually won
anything before.
Okay, well,
you still haven't.
I'm just listing
the nominees,
so not a great time
to get cocky.
Okay.
Christine Hollinsworth.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
PELTON:
Britney Baker.
Miss Danielle Harman.
Amy Sm--
Jeff Winger,
do not get back with Slater.
I love you.
CHANG:
Psst, psst. Britta. Britta.
Your lipstick looks better.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, man.
How's it going?
Uh, don't shoot the messenger
but everyone at this dance
is kind of waiting
for your reaction to all this.
Look, I'm trying to think,
okay?
Yeah, that's cool.
Take your time.
[WHISPERING]
How's it going? You look great.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Very Fatal Attraction.
Oh. Thanks.
[GRUNTS]
What's wrong with you?
I'm sick.
I don't know why.
Have you considered the 60-inch
diameter cookie you're eating?
How can something
that's delicious make me sick?
Unless too much of a good thing
is actually a bad thing.
My friendship with Abed
is a giant cookie.
I kinda got my own thing
going on now.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
[♪♪♪]
First of all, I'm flattered.
Second,
have you ever heard of e-mail?
You love me?
Do you love me?
I have something to say.
Jeff, I love you.
Ugh. I wonder
where she got that from.
I'm sorry. Do you have a patent
on loving people?
Would you like a patent
in getting your ass kicked?
[GIBBERS]
Okay, okay.
Can you stand over there?
[SIGHS]
And can you sit down, please?
[BRITTA SIGHS]
[SIGHS]
Jeffrey, choose Britta.
Yeah, Team Britta.
MAN:
Britta's lame.
Team Slater.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Bring Conan back.
[CROWD CHEERS]
It's been, uh, a great year.
Can't hear you.
No one can hear you.
I'm just gonna sneak
right up here and give you this.
Uh-- Hi, it's, uh--
Oh, come on,
who are you choosing?
[♪♪♪]
I-- I don't know.
Oh.
[CROWD BOOING]
PELTON:
Come on, Jeffrey.
[BOOING CONTINUES]
Everybody close
their faces.
He's got a lot on his mind.
Leave him alone.
I got it from here.
My name is Professor Ian Duncan,
and I would like
to rap for you.
No.
Drop a beat.
[RAP MUSIC PLAYS
OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ My name is Ian Duncan
And I'm here to say ♪
♪ I'm going to rap to the beat
In a rapping way ♪
♪ I've got a real big penis
And I drink lots of tea ♪
Okay, okay. No, no.
You know what, Duncan?
That's enough.
You have a problem.
Oh. I have a problem?
Yes.
Who is it here
who has a Dalmatian fetish?
Oh, okay. Okay.
That is an oversimplification,
and you are suspended.
Oh, come on.
You're not a teacher anymore.
What's this?
A roll of quarters. Why?
[GRUNTS]
Friends, help me, friends.
[ALL YELLING]
I'll do it.
I'll move in with you.
Fantastic, buddy.
Come over on Saturday?
My tailor will fit you
for a uniform.
[SHOUTING AND GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
I thought you left.
I couldn't go.
What happened?
I guess,
as we were driving away,
I finally started
living in the moment
and I realized that,
in the moment,
Greendale is where I belong.
What are you doing out here?
Oh, you know,
Britta and Slater
told me they loved me.
Really?
Yeah.
What did you do?
I ran away.
I don't know. It's hard.
Slater makes me feel
like I do
when I write
my New Year's resolutions.
She makes me feel
like the guy I want to be.
And Britta makes me
feel like the guy
I am three weeks
after New Year's,
when I'm back to hitting
my snooze button
and screening my
Mom's phone calls.
Back to who I really am.
So do you try to evolve,
or do you try to know
what you are?
I don't know.
I wish I could live two lives.
One of me would go with Vaughn,
one of me could stay here.
One of me could
be back with Slater,
and the other could try it
with Britta.
Then we could all get together
for some weird foursome.
[LAUGHS]
Um, I guess I gotta go
deal with it.
Good luck.
Um,
I'm glad you're staying.
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
Oh, my God. I'm finally popular
enough to be in the yearbook.
What do you mean video yearbook?
Where do I sign?
Photo not available.
This better not be one of those
take-your-top-off videos.
I don't believe in yearbooks.
I just want people
to remember
there's a guy
in between these things.
What a year.
Only two pregnancy scares.
I give this year
a D for delightful.
I can't believe
I spent 10 bucks on this.
I don't know
any of these people.