[ALARM CLOCK BEEPING]
And we're back.
[THE FRATELLIS'
"BABY FRATELLI" PLAYING]
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
♪ I said, oh, my
Oh, no, not I ♪
♪ I was just busy
Watching everyone go by ♪
♪ She got my number
Though I can't stand her ♪
♪ I can't help diggin' her
I hope I guess I wonder ♪
♪ And though it's clear
You want me dear ♪
PELTON [OVER PA]:
Welcome, students,
new and old,
to another fall semester
at Greendale.
It's time for clean slates
and fresh starts.
Celebrate your fresh start
tonight
at the Fresh-Start Dance
in the cafeteria.
The same cafeteria
where Britta Perry
professed her love
to Jeff Winger
who then walked out on her.
Unforgettable.
Plus, free punch
and Fresh-Start cookies
tonight
at the Fresh-Start Dance.
Look at us, living together,
driving to school together.
I know,
we're like Batman and Shaft.
Batman actually had a guy.
His name was Robin.
He rode around with him.
Troy, Batman's friend
didn't have to be Robin,
he could've been Shaft,
Dolemite, Leroy Brown.
Don't let society
limit your people.
[ANNIE CHUCKLES]
"Batman and Shaft," wow.
Reading Troy's Twitter
where he posts
everything Pierce says?
Yeah, it's hilarious.
[SCREAMING]
Hey.
Hello, Annie.
I like your hair.
Thank you, Abed.
You're welcome.
Jeffrey, hello.
How was your summer?
I live with you.
JEFF: How was your summer?
ABED: Great.
SHIRLEY:
Oh, okay.
PIERCE:
Hey.
ABED:
It's good to be back here.
SHIRLEY: I know.
Okay.
So you guys ready
for whatever Anthropology is?
We should wait for Britta.
Do we know
she's coming back?
She never returned my calls
or e-mails.
Me neither.
It's not gonna be the same
without her.
Did you guys see Toy Story 3?
Yes.
Oh, I loved Toy Story 3.
It was amazing, I love--
BRITTA: Hey!
Whoa!
Oh!
Hey, Toy Story-- Britta.
How's it going?
Okay, yeah, yeah.
I made an ass of myself
and Jeff at that dance.
I was caught up
in a competition
with his ex-girlfriend,
and I wish I could erase
the entire night.
And I owe you an apology.
I accept.
You don't owe us anything
and you don't have
to hide from us.
You? I'm hiding from them.
It's like high school
all over again.
Psycho Britta,
the walking freak show
for every Barbie
with a Cosmo subscription.
I don't mean to be a tool,
but you embarrassed me too,
so call it karma.
Whoa, boy,
I hope I'm not around
when you do mean
to be a tool.
Let's just put this behind us
and just walk to class, okay?
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
You're Britta Perry?
Yeah, what's it to you?
You're the coolest.
Right. Um...
At what exactly?
Being fearless, honest,
speaking from your heart.
"Jeff Winger, I love you."
Right.
My heart
may have overstated--
Do you sign stuff?
Now and again.
GIRL:
Awesome.
I don't like
where that's going.
I know, right? Heh.
Look,
um, remember the little talk
we had?
The one about discretion?
Yes. Stop that.
We agreed you and I kissing
was a mistake.
If anyone were to find out,
I would be tarred, feathered,
and put on websites people
check when buying a house.
It's forgotten,
Jeff, jeez.
I'm not some love-struck
teenybopper.
But we didn't just kiss,
we Frenched.
I checked the make-out meter
in this month's issue of
National Review.
I don't like
where that's going.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Señor Chang.
Oh, wait, I guess
it's not señor anymore.
What should we call you?
Student Chang?
Two-Credits-Into-
a-Music-Major Chang?
How about not calling me
anything? Hmm?
Why are you guys
in this class?
We chose it together.
The real question is,
why are you in it?
Oh, you missed us?
Oh.
Don't flatter yourself.
Have you checked
the course description?
Ancient weaponry.
Genital mutilation.
This subject's
talking my Chang-uage.
Ugh.
[ALL CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING]
I don't get it.
Star-Burns has grown reliant
on his sideburns
but craves identity beyond them,
so he added a hat.
No, what's up
with Britta mania?
Oh, that's even simpler.
Britta put herself out there
and you walked away,
making her the underdog,
the Aniston.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah.
Have any hillbilly cousins?
I wish, why?
A wealthy uncle,
or buddy that may have
had a sex change?
Why are you mining my life
for sitcom scenarios?
I'm excited about the year,
looking to improve.
I'm hoping we can move away
from the relationship-y stuff
into fast-paced escapades.
What is it exactly
that separates man
from animal?
Divorce.
[LAUGHING]
[STUDENTS GASP]
[WHEEZING]
Tools.
Like this blowgun I used
to hunt monkeys
with the Korubo
in the Amazon.
My name
is Professor June Bauer,
and this semester
I will guide you
to the threshold
of your humanity
where you will lock eyes
with the shrieking,
blood-drenched,
sister-raping beasts
from which we sprang.
You will also have
to make a diorama.
[CLASS GROANS]
For your first assignment,
I would like you to form tribes
of no more than eight,
and if you can,
mix up the races.
You'll be surprised
at how quickly things
get awkward.
[♪♪♪]
Now that Troy's off the streets
and living with me,
he's learning
about the world.
Yeah. Tell me again
why Jewish people
wear yarmulkes.
Half a hat, saves money.
Thank you.
"Half a hat"?
That is so offensive.
I love Old White Man Says.
Find an eighth dork
for your tribe of dorks?
I think you took
Anthropology
because you wanna be
in our group
but are too proud to ask.
Keep dreaming, Winger.
Would somebody with
too much pride do this?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Current balance: $23.20.
Consider yourself Chang'd.
Mac and cheese, please.
Sorry, looks like your food
just walked out on you.
Same way you did Britta.
[WOMEN LAUGHING]
Hey, can we talk?
Oh, now he wants to talk.
No, it's fine,
I'll be right back.
Man,
you got some passionate fans.
Eh. It'll blow over.
Well, would you mind
helping it blow over?
My stock is kind
of plummeting around here.
Oh, I don't mean
to sound like a tool,
but maybe it's karma.
I know you're excited
to be popular with women,
but don't get too high
on your own drama.
[LOUDLY]
High on my own drama?!
[CROWD GASPS]
The people's champion.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Sorry, man,
I gotta go where the heat is.
Jeff Winger, you're a jerk.
[♪♪♪]
She's turned every woman
against me.
Not every woman, not the one
that deserves to be with you.
All women
deserve to be with me,
and vice versa.
Granted,
but who doesn't
eventually settle down?
I don't, and I never will.
And if I did--
[♪♪♪]
If I did,
I could beat Britta
at her own game.
Oh, good.
Yeah,
you better take a hike.
Do you know where
the cleanest bathroom is?
Teacher's lounge.
Thank you.
Don't be shy, come on up,
have a sip.
The yogi of India swear
by its restorative powers.
Okay,
more of my urine for me.
Now
for your tribe's assignment.
This box contains
nine different tools,
all of them important
to humanity's survival.
One of them
is the most important of all.
Your tribe's assignment
for tomorrow
is to tell me
which tool that is.
Questions?
I have a question.
But not for you.
It's for Britta.
Britta.
I love you.
[CLASS GASPS]
I know this puts you
in an awkwardly
powerful position,
but I have to know, right now,
in front of everyone,
do you love me too?
More than anything
in the world.
[♪♪♪]
Really?
Yeah.
So it begins.
Hmm.
The greatest relationship
ever known.
[BOTH GROANING]
This is making me sick.
[SIPPING LOUDLY]
I'm gonna love you forever.
Good,
JEFF:
I don't believe you.
Why, don't you want me to?
No, I do. Bring it.
Doesn't it make you
wanna cry?
Something like that.
Excuse me.
I downloaded a song
that makes me think of you.
Let's listen to it,
each using one ear bud.
Would you consider
spinning off with me?
We could
open a hair salon.
I don't understand.
Is this you being meta?
I wanted to come out
having adventures,
like paintball.
This is boring.
SHIRLEY:
That's selfish, Abed.
If you were a friend,
you'd see their relationship
as an adventure.
I hadn't thought
about it that way.
Oh! Look at how they walk.
Clearly,
the most important tool
is the cross,
representing Christianity.
It's an ax.
It's an ax?
Maybe the telescope.
Look through it backwards,
shrink your enemies.
PIERCE:
I'll show you the tool
that's most important
to our survival,
but fair warning,
it's my penis.
[CHUCKLES]
[CELL PHONES
BEEPING AND BUZZING]
[ALL EXCEPT PIERCE LAUGHING]
Old White Man.
JEFF: Sorry I'm late.
I was in my car
loving Britta.
I just love you too much.
Not half as much as me.
Aww.
Do you think
you'll marry Britta?
I'd like to see
someone stop me.
I just peed a little.
Then here, propose.
Oh.
[♪♪♪]
I got it, I got it, got it.
Jeff Winger,
will you marry me?
Yeah, of course.
No problem. No problem.
[BOTH SCREAM]
Perfect,
I'll be right back.
[SHIRLEY &amp; ANNIE
SCREAMING]
Thank the Lord.
I was so worried
about your souls,
ever since you had
pre-marital sex on the table.
TROY &amp; ANNIE:
Oh!
Awesome.
You told Shirley?
No need for secrecy now.
It was during
the paintball game.
Was there anything
you didn't win that day?
Oh, my God!
You slept with her
and then kissed me?
What?
♪ Now they're in so deep ♪
♪ You know
She's such a fool for him ♪
♪ She has a ring
Around her finger ♪
♪ And Abed
Hired an Irish singer ♪
♪ Britta's marrying
Britta's marrying ♪
Jeffrey Winger ♪
What the hell is this?
A wedding episode.
Abed, there's no wedding.
Cold feet? Talk with your
best man, George Clooney.
What's up?
He's an impersonator.
But still razzle-dazzle,
right?
Abed.
Hmm?
Jeff made out with Annie.
What? When? Where?
Yeah, where?
That's inappropriate.
I'm assuming on the mouth.
After the Transfer Dance.
I tell you that I love you,
then you go and stick
your tongue into a teenager?
What is wrong with you,
Jeffrey?
Shirley, since you have
clearly failed to grasp
the central insipid metaphor
of those Twilight books
you devour,
let me explain it to you.
Men are monsters
who crave young flesh,
the end.
At least we have the decency
to keep it a secret.
Instead of blurting
"I love you"
to everyone
who sleeps with us.
Oh, please,
I never loved you.
Ah-ha!
I win, I win, I win.
In your face.
So this was all a game?
Everything they do
is some sick competition.
Like you hate
competition.
How long did it take you
to kiss Jeff
after
I told him I loved him?
First Vaughn, now Jeff.
I better not smile
at that wall outlet
or you'll fry
your tongue off!
TROY:
Way to hog all the girls.
When there's three
doughnuts,
don't eat one
and lick another.
Anyone object to us being
referred to as doughnuts?
Sorry we can't all be
as honorable as you
and post Pierce quotes
all day on Twitter.
Wow,
is that your lame attempt
to try and pass
the hot seat to me?
Nice try.
Wait,
I'm Old White Man Says?
No wonder he says
everything I'm thinking.
You bastard.
I'm just sharing
what you say.
Yeah, well, what if I shared
all the stuff you say?
He thinks all dogs are boys
and all cats are girls.
There's no way
to disprove that.
Have you ever seen
a cat penis?
Where you going?
By the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you
canceled.
Oh, good.
Yeah, Abed, cancel us.
Why don't you take
your cutesy
"I can't tell life
from TV" gimmick with you?
You know,
it's very "season one."
I can tell life from TV,
Jeff.
TV makes sense,
it has structure, logic, rules,
and likable leading men.
In life, we have this.
We have you.
[♪♪♪]
Ahem. I'm on the clock
for another hour
if you want me to do
some Batman lines.
[♪♪♪]
Not sitting
with your little group?
The group is done.
Yeah, well, missionary
accomplished, right?
What does that mean?
Come on, I know you
and Britta did it.
Isn't the reason
you got with those people
because you wanted
to bang the blond?
Now I hear that you
Frenched the brunette.
What more could you have
gotten out of that group?
BAUER:
Good morning, class.
Let's dive in
and hear the results
of your assignment.
Who wants to go first?
I don't know, Mr. Winger,
the last time I called on you,
I kind of got
what the Maku-Maku call
"dirt-roaded."
[IN SINGSONG VOICE]
Using it.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
[MOUTHING]
Come on up.
It was a trick question.
The tool most important
to humanity's survival
wasn't any of the nine
in the box.
Go on.
The most important tool
is respect.
Ha! Gay.
And the reason I know
respect is a tool
is because it is clearly
not a natural thing
and we forget
to use it all the time.
And then we start competing
with each other,
exploiting each other,
humiliating each other
and controlling each other.
And we lose each other.
And without each other,
we'll go extinct.
And that's a fact.
Heh. A gay fact.
That's my answer, professor.
Hmm.
Well, that's one answer.
Here's the one
I had in mind.
Combining all nine tools,
you get this,
a deadlier weapon
than any one item in the box.
So I'm gonna use this
to attack you,
and you use respect
to defend yourself.
Uh-- Oh-- Uh--
[CLASS GASPING]
BRITTA: Oh, my God.
SHIRLEY: Jeffrey.
I respect you.
That's why you fail.
[CHOKING]
BRITTA: Oh, my God.
SHIRLEY: Jeffrey.
He's passing out.
TROY:
Stay with us, buddy.
Hello.
Oh, thank God.
What happened?
Professor Bauer
got suspended,
and we got an A
on our assignment.
Did someone throw urine
in my face?
I surprise myself
under pressure.
Jeff, about the assignment,
we decided
you had the right answer.
We need more respect
and a little less passion.
Which will be easy because
I think you're gross now.
Awesome.
I'm gonna delete
that Twitter account.
Your friendship
is more important
than 600,000 strangers.
Whoa, whoa.
Are you saying 600,000 people
read what I say on Twitter?
Well,
we gotta cash in on that.
How about Old White Man Says,
the TV Show?
GROUP:
No.
TROY:
Who would watch that?
Speaking of bad development
strategy, I owe you an apology.
I was trying so hard
to make our week great,
I didn't realize
something great.
An old woman
drinking her own pee.
You're right.
That's true.
Guys?
I took Anthropology
because I wanna be a part
of your study group.
[ALL MUTTERING]
Now I gotta do the honest thing
and just ask.
Is there any room
in this pocket
for a little spare Chang?
Uh-- Look, we've been
through a lot today.
Give us a little time
to think it over.
Totally, man.
Just think about it.
Take your time and let me know.
Bye.
See you, Chang.
CHANG:
Bye.
Aww. Poor guy.
We'll let him in eventually.
Says who?
We have the strength
to survive anything.
What's the worst
that can happen?
Yeah, that's true.
Good point.
[♪♪♪]
[IN MEAN VOICE]
I told you they hate you.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
No, they said they
just needed more time.
[IN MEAN VOICE]
Time? They destroyed your life.
How much time
before we take revenge?
[NORMAL VOICE]
But they're my friends.
[IN MEAN VOICE]
I'm your only friend.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
No.
No!
[BEATBOXING]
♪ Kingdom: Animalia
Phylum: Chordata ♪
♪ The class is ♪
♪ Mammalia ♪
♪ 'Cuz boobies we gotta ♪
♪ Order is Primate
Family: Hominidae ♪
♪ The genus is ♪
♪ Homo ♪
♪ But you know
you're into me ♪
♪ Because I am in the species
Known as Sapien ♪
♪ Dogs used to eat me ♪
♪ But now
They bring the paper in ♪
♪ It's gonna take a lot
To get me away from you ♪
♪ Damn, damn ♪
BOTH:
♪ There's nothing
That a hundred men or more ♪
♪ Could ever do ♪
♪ Sapien ♪
TROY &amp; ABED:
♪ I bless the rains
Down in Africa ♪
♪ Oh, bless the rains ♪
TROY &amp; ABED:
♪ I bless the rains
Down in Africa ♪
ALL:
♪ I bless the rains
Down in Africa ♪
♪ Africa ♪