[♪♪♪]
Oh, what are you guys
doing together,
just the two of you?
We're gonna raise money
to help with the oil spill.
Making this display to show
how serious the problem is.
Oh, yeah. Each drop represents
10,000 gallons of oil.
Ooh.
Oh.
I'm so glad
this overshadowed Haiti.
I didn't have ideas
for that.
Yay to having fun in pairs.
What up, party people?
You got a Band-Aid on your arm.
Be careful shaving.
I wax, dummy.
This is from a blood test.
Oh, no. I knew it.
Things were going
too well for you.
Oh, no, no, just a physical.
Even a Ferrari
needs a tune-up.
Are you guys
moonshiners now?
No,
just the two of them.
We're raising money
for the oil spill.
Did you even know?
Uh, yeah, I have
the AOL homepage bookmarked.
Did you even know
about the ostrich
that raised a tiger cub?
Troy, what's wrong?
I just saw a dead body.
Told you not to use
the east stairwell.
My pastor said
it's meth season.
You know I'm living
with Pierce now,
so this morning I went
to do laundry in the garage
and I found his mom, dead.
Oh.
Troy, that's terrible.
Well, she had been in bad shape
for a while,
so I guess she crawled
out there to die like a cat.
I've never been close
to a dead body.
Oh, pumpkin.
She was so cold and grey.
I saw her underwear.
[WHISTLING]
Jeez, who died?
Pierce, we're so sorry to hear
about your mom.
Why?
Losing a loved one
is always difficult.
What? My mom isn't dead.
But when Troy found her,
he said--
Her heart, lungs, kidneys
and brain have stopped working.
And another way
of saying that would be?
She used up
her organic body.
By dying in it.
Wrong. She's alive.
Mom was a part
of my Buddhist church.
She's a Level Five Laser Lotus,
same as me.
When a Level Five's body
stops functioning,
it's vaporized
in the Temple of Renewal
and stored
in an energon pod.
In a few years,
when our technology advances,
they'll extract
her body vapors,
re-condense it to a solid.
Before you know it,
Mom will be back in the kitchen
making Troy
and me sandwiches.
Heh.
[CRYING]
SHIRLEY:
Pumpkin. It's okay.
Oh, sweetie.
Did you guys hear
about that turtle in China?
Two packs a day.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
If you guys let me get
to the can opener,
I can feed you.
We have to do something
about Pierce.
He thinks his mom
isn't dead.
He's gone crazy.
"--er"?
He won't even let us have
a memorial service.
I was halfway done
with the collage.
He hasn't cried yet.
I'm told that's not normal.
Who's normal, Abed?
Baptists are,
but that's beside the point.
Everybody has some service
for the departed.
Eskimos, witch doctors,
Jewish people.
Cool, we made the list.
The point being,
death needs to be coped with,
not ignored.
Otherwise why did mankind
concoct all these religions?
You wanna rephrase that?
Oh, I'm sorry, humankind.
You think you're real smart.
Guys, guys, guys.
Did we learn nothing
from last Christmas?
I don't see much difference
between Pierce's religion
and anybody else's.
You're not listening,
because his has lasers.
You guys make fun of me
for not caring about religion.
But at least
I'm dedicated enough
to not caring to let you
have your own beliefs.
Can't Pierce have his?
Can't you be cool like me?
Hello?
He ends so many
of his speeches that way.
Morning, guys.
Morning, Pierce. How's Mom?
Terrific. Her body is being
vaporized as we speak.
What does that feel like?
It's the greatest feeling
ever.
Like the second when the fudge
on your sundae is still hot,
or when you're the first one
to break in a new boob job.
You're free from the burden
of your earthly body.
It is a burden.
Greetings, class.
I am Dr. Ian Duncan.
Now, I don't normally teach
Anthropology,
but apparently, Professor Bauer
tried to strangle Mr. Winger
and has been put on leave
with pay.
So, what is anthropology?
Seriously, does anyone know?
You, in the boobs.
It's the study of humanity.
Wow.
Wow, I thought psychology
was a racket.
Well, well.
I heard there was a drunk limey
teaching this class.
I'm not drunk
and I can prove it.
I blew beneath the limit
this morning.
That's reassuring.
Also I would like
everyone here to know
that this man assaulted me
last year.
And I have
a restraining order,
so I can have him expelled
if he comes within--
Twenty-five feet.
Abed.
ABED: Yep.
[♪♪♪]
Proceed, Dr. Teeth.
BRITTA:
It is the single
largest disaster
in recorded history.
It is worse
than 50 Exxon Valdez spills.
You don't have
to yell at us.
Nobody is on the other side
of this issue.
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
And the pelicans
are covered in oil.
Everyone likes pelicans.
They bring babies.
That's storks.
Right.
Well, we still like them.
Heh, heh, heh.
Yeah, we do.
I'm gonna give you
another 20.
Aw. Thank you so much.
[♪♪♪]
I'm here for my test results,
if you haven't framed them yet.
Hey, gorgeous.
Jeff, you have something
very infectious.
What?
Charm.
[LAUGHING]
You got me, Jackie.
Seriously,
everything looks great.
You're an incredible
specimen.
Even your moles are shaped
like little hearts.
Only thing I suggest,
see a doctor.
And get a prescription
for cholesterol medication.
What? Why?
Your cholesterol's
a little high.
No big deal.
Eat some egg whites.
But I don't understand.
Wait, did I accidentally
tell you you have AIDS?
I've done that before.
I mean, it doesn't--
I treat my body
like a temple.
I can't be the first person
to tell you
that the temple
doesn't last forever.
I mean, it's made of hamburger.
This is a Temple of Doom.
And like the real
Temple of Doom,
it represents
the inconvenient fact
that all good things,
be they people
or movie franchises,
eventually collapse
into sagging,
sloppy, rotten piles
of hard-to-follow nonsense.
I need to be alone.
Uh,
you can do that by leaving.
Okay. Let's get going.
These Paps aren't gonna
smear themselves.
JEFF:
There is no God!
Tell us how you really feel.
Am I right?
[♪♪♪]
Did you get the results
of your blood test?
I'm fine.
I figured.
Thank you for wising us up.
We were being judgmental
about Pierce's religion.
But the fact
is Jesus accepts--
The fact
is everyone's dying.
And we all have these notions
that we're the exception,
but we're as wrong
as we are dead.
That's nice.
How's it going
with the side project
that the two of you
are doing?
It's great. I made $236,
plus Britta's makes--
Well, all totaled,
we're close to 250,
right, Britta?
Mm-hm.
Greendale cares
about this issue.
Yeah,
I don't think that's it.
What do you mean?
Come on, Annie.
Guys are giving you money
because of the sexy
schoolgirl routine.
I have a routine?
Yeah.
The one where you use
posture as an excuse
to stick out your chest
and you laugh at guys'
unfunny jokes,
pretending not to know
that they have a sock at home
with your name on it.
Um, that's me.
And if a guy wants
to make a puppet of me,
that's hardly your concern.
I may just be
an outsider here
because I was never called
to participate,
but it seems to me
that Britta's upset
because she's raising
less money than you.
I'm raising less money
because I'm not jump-starting
date rapists.
Ooh-hoo.
Bitter much?
Say "bitter much" much?
Say "say 'bitter much' much"
much?
[SIGHS]
It's not my fault.
I used to wear a back brace.
That's why.
What's with the lava lamp?
It's not a lava lamp.
It's my mom.
Oh, snap. Wait, what?
The temple
finished vaporizing her.
This is Mom's energon pod.
That's her vapor
in those bubbles.
I'm sure that thing was free,
right?
PIERCE:
Energon doesn't grow on trees,
Jeff.
It's harvested by super bees
in Buddha's meteor crater.
Which is at the foot
of Mount Sky Mall
in The Sharper Image Valley?
Sorry, I overslept.
The sidewalk is more
comfortable than it looks.
Drunk.
Shut up. So where
did we get to yesterday?
You are drunk and stupid.
Actually, Ben,
I do have a wee bit
of a headache,
so if you could just--
Um...
Isn't that interesting?
I have a right to be here,
sir.
You do, you do.
And I do hope
you have very good hearing.
[GASPS]
Bastard.
So where did we get to
yesterday?
We were talking
about humanity,
which starts with birth
and ends with death.
DUNCAN:
True, all life ends in death,
which we as a species
are cursed with knowing,
resulting in something.
Again, this is really
not my field.
Professor, what would you say
might be the difference
between a religion
and a cult?
Why don't we open that
to the floor
since I don't know and the book
for this class is expensive?
Well, I would say a cult might,
for instance,
sell you a tube of Jell-O
and tell you
your mother is in it.
Jeffrey.
Are we thinly veiling
personal conflict
and passing it off
as a lesson?
Because if so,
please continue.
Reformed Neo-Buddhism
is not a cult.
It is a new way
of looking at the world,
emphasizing empowerment.
Like a video game?
Yes, Troy,
very much like a video game.
You gain levels
and at a certain point,
you actually can eat
a ghost.
What?
I wanna eat a ghost.
No, no, do not let him
pollute your brain
with this crap, Troy.
It's okay to ask questions.
ABED: I have a question.
Your mother went
from solid to vapor.
Do people ever take
liquid form,
like creatures in The Abyss
or Children's Tylenol?
It's a good question.
Actually, when Buddha returns,
we all take liquid form
and merge into a shimmering
ocean of knowledge,
which, according to scripture,
tastes like Hawaiian Punch.
[STUDENTS CHATTERING]
BRITTA:
Hawaiian Punch.
If you're curious, come to
my church's Open Hive tomorrow.
You know, wine, beer
and free credit checks.
How much wine and beer
per person?
Oh, come on.
We're having a con-- What?
Excuse me,
is this Anesthesiology?
Yes. Yes, it is.
Just go with this.
It's really sad.
I've seen it.
Anything helps.
Just anything you
can give would be really--
I don't have--
[♪♪♪]
Hey. I, like, need you
to save the pelicans.
They're all feathery
and pelican-y.
I love them.
Thank you.
Wow, it really is easy
to raise money
when you sell out
your gender.
It's even easier
when you're not standing
next to this:
Hey, jerk.
You're stupid.
Give me money.
I know more than you.
I don't know anything.
I need boys.
Saving the planet
makes my back hurt.
I obviously don't need guys
for anything.
That's why
I wear stripper boots
and eat only celery
and mustard for lunch.
Oh, I never stop smiling.
I never start.
My sweaters keep shrinking.
I get up an hour early
to ever-so-slightly curl
my hair.
[GASPS]
Yeah,
you're both so different.
Skinny bitches.
DUNCAN:
Hello, Billionaire Boys Club.
What happened
in class today?
You pulled 40 minutes
of anesthesiology
out of your ass.
Yeah, I did.
But I meant
your elderly friend.
MAN:
Are you okay? Are you okay?
Do you know how many times
I haven't eaten a doughnut?
I do not.
How I got teased in grade school
for dabbing my pizza
with napkins?
I've suffered.
I've denied myself.
Mm-hm.
Because the rules said,
if I did that,
I would live longer.
But then,
halfway through the game,
I get this little update.
That it doesn't matter
what I do.
I could eat powdered bran
every day
while you suck down pudding
and I still might die first.
It's unfair.
I want my doughnuts back.
Well, I think you're being
a little childish and--
Hold on.
I need to use my force field
to prevent Chang
from getting food.
[♪♪♪]
[CHANG GASPING AND GRUNTING]
[CHANG GROANING]
DUNCAN:
Now, where were we?
Look, the way I see it,
while claiming
to have no religion,
you were actually devoutly
worshipping yourself.
And now that your god
has high cholesterol,
you're trying to
kick Pierce's in the balls.
You're right.
All I've been trying to do
is crush Pierce's faith
to feel better about dying.
And?
Now that I realize
that that was my goal,
I can really roll up my sleeves
and get it done.
There it is.
Thank you.
Welcome.
No, that wasn't what I was--
Actually, I don't care.
Hey, girls,
guess who found Buddha.
Hey.
We're on our way to Pierce's
Buddhist Open Hive.
First I'm taking these
fellas for ice cream
as an apology for questioning
Pierce's faith.
Pierce says
there's this 69th flavor
I need to try.
I am excited.
Hey guys,
my car's over there.
Cool.
Guess what.
I'm not actually taking them
for ice cream.
I am taking them
to the county morgue
where I have confirmed
that Pierce's mother's
very un-vaporized corpse
will be lying
on a stainless-steel slab
for all to see.
Surprise.
Welcome to reality.
Welcome to death.
Have fun.
Good luck.
Wow,
you guys are real downers.
I can't believe I made out
with both of you.
Ugh.
I'll check the basket.
Sorry, I almost arched
my back a little.
I know you hate that.
I should count it,
since I'm a calculating bitch.
No, I should,
since I'm the one
who's whoring out
our gender.
Give that back.
I'm gonna count it!
Let go!
Give me that!
[BOTH SCREAM]
Ugh.
Oh!
Oh, yeah?
You think this is funny?
You think it's funny?
Get off of me.
Come here, you little brat.
ANNIE:
I'm a brat?
BRITTA:
What the--?
ANNIE:
I hate you!
Now,
this is why I came to America.
TROY:
Maybe we should listen
to some music.
No problem.
I brought the jam book
from the Pierce-mobile.
I could play some
of the old stuff,
but you guys would make fun
of me. Heh, heh, heh.
So I'll throw you a bone
and put in some Loggins.
This ice cream place is far.
Trust me,
it's worth it.
What's this?
This is Mom's handwriting.
Is that what you were doing
in the garage, you silly goose?
She spent
her last moments alive
making a CD?
That is gangster.
PIERCE'S MOM [ON CD]:
Pierce, you've found the CD,
which means I'm dead.
Vaporized.
I'm not vaporized.
I'm gone, Pierce.
Gone forever
and that's how I like it.
Life is only worth a damn
because it's short.
It's designed to be consumed,
used, spent, lived, felt.
We're supposed to fill it
with every mistake and miracle
we can manage.
And then we're supposed
to let go.
I can't force you to do that
for yourself, Pierce.
But you can't force me
to stay.
And if you unscrew the top
of that stupid thing,
you'll see it was made
in China.
I love you, son.
Goodbye.
I'll play myself out.
[KU'S "BEST OF THE BEST"
PLAYING]
♪ They say I'm cooler than cool
That I'm the best of the best ♪
♪ 'Cause they know that
When I do it ♪
♪ I'm-a do it to death ♪
[MUSIC STOPS]
[SIGHS]
Well, that proves one thing.
That woman was really losing
her marbles toward the end.
You seriously still think
she's in there?
Why wouldn't I?
No reason.
So where's this
ice cream place?
Yeah.
Oh. Um--
You know, I think
I actually saw a better one
back there.
The place I was gonna take you
is kind of depressing.
[♪♪♪]
ANNIE:
Oh, can we get
a little more sawdust
on that storm gutter?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
I just got jealous of you.
No,
but you totally called me on
what I was doing and--
I only kissed Jeff
to see if I could do it.
I wanna be cool
and sexy like you.
I can't believe
how gross I am.
I only slept with Jeff
because I hate myself.
That's why I got after you
for raising money.
I'm twice as gross.
No.
And you know the reason
that we raised more money
in five minutes
of oil wrestling
than in two days
of fundraising?
Because men
are even grosser?
And when we forget that,
they win.
BOTH:
Aw.
PIERCE:
Yeah, all right,
all right, all right.
Yeah, do it.
Oh, so you got
actual ice cream?
Yeah, with peanut butter
and hot fudge.
What the hell, right?
Nobody lives forever.
No offense.
Think what you want,
it's a free country.
I barely saw you this week,
Abed.
What have you been up to?
Not much.
Hm.
What?
Whoa, busted, 25 feet.
Which puts you in violation
of this restraining order
I filed against you
for abusing me
with your
restraining order.
Ah!
Mutually assured
destruction.
Well played, Chang.
Thank you.
That-- That means a lot.
Do you mind
getting a quick photo of me
with the oily co-eds?
Center button. You're the man.
Okay. No problem.
What, what?
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
He's not a projection.
He's the British guy
pretending to be Tom Berenger.
It was a mislead.
That's the whole point
of Inception,
subversion of reality.
He hasn't seen it yet.
[SCOFFS]