City College
has a space simulator.
We know, close the door.
As I was saying, on Monday,
City College will be unveiling
the City College Cosmic
Pioneer,
their very own orbital launch
simulator.
Pretty soon, they will have
an astronaut on their brochure,
and we will still be bragging
about our Foosball table.
What do you think happens
to enrollment then?
I don't know about
you gentlemen,
but I love my campus.
I don't wanna watch
it become
a City College
parking lot.
Well, what can we do?
We can launch
our own space simulator.
Before they simulate their
launch on Monday,
we simulate a launch
this weekend.
We make Greendale,
not City College,
the first community college
to pretend
to put a man in space.
Do we even have a simulator?
We can get one.
In 1980,
the county museum had
a state-of-the-art
space mission simulator,
sponsored
by Kentucky Fried Chicken,
called The Kentucky
Fried Chicken Eleven Herbs
and Space Experience.
Gentlemen, Greendale's future.
MEN: Oh.
Actually, that photo is from
past. Here's one more current.
MAN: It's seen better days.
I admit, it could use good wash.
And I've got just the crew
to wash it.
[♪♪♪]
Can we stop walking
in slo-mo now?
Twenty more yards.
You guys are walking
in slo-mo?
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
PELTON:
You guys are an hour late.
ANNIE:
Abed kept making us
redo our walk.
I think you know
the reason
this group has been
chosen for this job.
To atone for the obscene entry
you submitted
in the Greendale school
flag contest. That's right,
I know that
this isn't a symbol
for the crossroads of ideas,
I now know it's a butt.
[SNICKERING]
PELTON:
Yeah, keep snickering.
Pack yourselves with peanuts
and really be satisfied,
but guess what.
This won.
This is now our school flag
forever. Proud of yourselves?
How do you know
it was our design?
We submitted it anonymously.
Whoops.
One of you actually
came forward.
What?
Now, somewhere beneath
this dirt
is Greendale's newest pride.
And my hope is that
while you scrub it,
you will find the school pride
in your hearts.
After we clean it,
can we go inside?
No. That is a job
for some upstanding students
who are training right now
in the Simulator Simulator.
Great job on this.
Hard to believe I'm not really
not really in space.
I expect this craft
to be squeaky clean
in time for the pretend launch
in front of the press at 3:00.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to make this a butt flag.
I remember this thing
from high school.
During field trips,
we used to sneak inside
and get to praying.
Oh, that's nice.
We should take
a coffee break.
Let's all get coffee.
Where are Troy and Abed?
They made their way into that
thing after the dean left.
What?
[♪♪♪]
Oh. It's more beautiful
than I imagined.
You've never been in it?
My dad never let me.
He had a grudge against
restaurants,
they almost wiped out
his falafel stand.
I memorized every detail of this
old girl on the Internet.
Guys, we can't be in here.
Then get out.
Wow, pretty well-preserved
for something survived the '80s.
And a local transient who
liked to collect doll heads.
PIERCE:
Ah. The '80s.
Our teen years, right,
everybody?
I feel like I'm underdressed
for this.
I'm gonna get something
from the dorm.
Guys, seriously, I have to ask
that we all step out of here.
You gonna tattle on us
like you did with the flag?
I didn't tattle,
but you shouldn't have made it.
If you love Greendale so much,
why don't you marry it?
Sorry, sorry, I'm a little
claustrophobic, that's all.
It's no big deal as long
as I'm standing near a door.
In closed situations
I get a little nuts
and I don't know
what's gonna--
Hey, hey, hey. No.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
Hello?
SANDERS [OVER SPEAKER]:
Greetings.
I am Systematic Android Network
Diode Energy Rocket System,
but you may call me
Sanders.
Sanders, Sanders,
this is Pierce Hawthorne.
Can I get this door open?
Look for the handle.
There's got to be a handle.
It was the '80s. Everybody
who made this was on cocaine.
We can't be in here.
Just as Kentucky Fried
Chicken's secret process
seals in the flavor,
I'm sealing the cabin's air
so you don't
explode on your journey.
What?
What does that mean?
Please find a seat,
strap yourself in
and wait
for Mission Control.
Okay, we gotta find a handle
on this door.
Guys, can we take
a mental step backwards
and realize we are simply in
a Winnebago and we'll be fine?
[THUDDING AND RUMBLING]
Oh, my God.
Please find a seat.
Strap yourself in and
wait for Mission Control.
I'm not strapping into a coffin.
We gotta get out of here.
I hope you've found a seat.
I want you to be safe.
Did you just threaten me?
Pierce, you're talking
to an Atari cartridge.
Sit down.
Ah!
Oh, we're moving.
This is part of
the simulation, right?
I don't think this is
a simulation.
I think we're being towed.
[♪♪♪]
Come on.
Hello?
You guys, forget it.
Whoever's towing us
can't hear us.
You know,
this is classic Greendale.
That place deserves
an anus flag.
Can anyone get a phone signal?
SHIRLEY &amp; BRITTA: No.
Mine's working, but it's that
black guy with the wrong number.
Pierce, I keep telling you
that that is an iPod,
and you are listening
to Wesley Snipes' audio book.
He sure hates the government.
This is a long shot,
but maybe if I do this,
it will solve everything.
[BEEPING]
Damn it.
This is all my fault.
Very much so.
Hey, when you go fishing,
sometimes you catch a boot.
PELTON [OVER RADIO]:
Where are you?
[PELTON'S VOICE BREAKING UP]
Where--?
Hello?
Where are you hoodlums?
Bring my spaceship back.
Uh... We are...
Forty light years outside
of the Buttermilk Nebula,
although it is possible...
Yeah, it's a sticker.
Hey, Terrible Dean.
This thing is being towed
with us in it.
Oh. Oh, okay, wait.
So handicap spots count
on Saturdays?
Assuming we don't wind up
in a compactor,
when we get back,
I am going to step on you.
As much as
I might enjoy that,
if you don't get back in time
for the launch,
City College wins, and Greendale
becomes just another school
on my resume that no one can
call because it doesn't exist.
Now tell me where you are.
In a moving canister with
no phone and no GPS
because the only window
is sealed shut.
[♪♪♪]
Hell-- Hello?
Jeffrey? Damn it.
It isn't sealed shut.
Hmm?
Window isn't sealed,
it slides open
when you complete
the simulation.
Well, can you talk them
through it? Hey, Abed.
If they can open that window,
they can tell us where they are,
and we can find them.
I was supposed
to be on that thing.
[♪♪♪]
I know how she works.
Hey, that's why they need you
to bring her home.
I'll get us some coffee.
[IN SINGSONG VOICE]
Psycho.
[♪♪♪]
ABED: Troy.
Abed?
You can get that window open
by doing the simulation.
Look at the panel,
tell me your recipe.
Original.
How many pieces?
TROY: Six.
Flavor?
TROY: Tasty.
We need to get up to delicious.
That makes sense.
SANDERS:
Excellent work, captain.
Now keep your herbs
and spices balanced
while the crew
helps you with teamwork.
Guys, we can get the window
open if you man your terminals
and we complete the simulation.
Yeah, I got a better idea.
[ANNIE YELLING]
Gooby dooby, gooby dooby.
We're all gonna die,
we're all gonna die.
My readings indicate
the need for cooperation.
I hate to pull rank on you, but
I need you to man your station.
I hate to pull reality on you,
but you got your rank, captain,
by sitting in the chair
with the largest knobs.
My readings indicate
Pierce.
[MOUTHS] What?
SANDERS: Pierce.
My readings indicate
you're going to die alone.
Why is he saying that?
Why is he saying that to me?
He's getting worse.
Almost there.
Stop talking, old man.
You can't make me stop,
Pierce,
because Troy is giving me
life force.
I knew it. I knew it.
Hey, hey.
Come on, Troy.
Abed.
Hold on, Troy.
[SCREAMING OVER RADIO]
ABED:
Kentucky One? Do you read me?
Kentucky One?
Kentucky One, do you read me?
Kentucky One, copy.
Kentucky, come in, Kentucky.
I've worked out a way to reroute
the power from the battery.
Reroute to what?
Everybody.
Here is the situation.
This is Greendale.
This is the maximum distance
from Greendale we can drive
to haul them back up here in
time for the simulated launch.
And these
are city impound lots,
any of which
might be their destination.
What are these other circles?
What circles?
Looks like you've circled
restrooms and truck stops,
there's another one.
Okay, that is a different side
of the map and that is
for a different project.
Why do they have star ratings?
Let's get to work, people.
Got it, talk to me, come on.
Well, we stopped moving.
Pierce has got space madness,
so he's old,
they're locking him up
in the back.
[PIERCE GRUNTS]
[SHIRLEY YELLS]
You can't do this to me.
We just did.
Guys, please.
You're becoming animals.
Oh, shut up, we wouldn't even
be here if it wasn't for you.
That's not true, we weren't
supposed to be in here
when it happened.
When what happened?
When we got towed?
How did you know
we were gonna get towed?
I set it up.
I called City College about
transferring and dean told me
that he would get me in
if I helped
sabotage Greendale's launch.
I was to make sure
nobody was around
so they could steal it.
And then you guys
were late, and then...
Wait, wait, you're
transferring? Why?
[MUTTERING]
You guys thought that
butt hole flag was so funny.
I respect you all
to let you hate yourselves,
but I respect myself too much
to let you hate my school.
[♪♪♪]
I'm not buying it.
Let's kill her.
Wait, City College
was behind this?
We gotta get back
in time for launch.
Why?
We earned the right
to pick on Greendale every day
by going there.
Our school may be a toilet,
but it's our toilet.
Nobody craps in it but us.
BRITTA: Yeah.
Now, that was inspiring.
Seriously?
Captain.
Get to your stations.
Thrusters.
Full.
Thermal shield.
On.
Navigation.
Three.
Chicken.
Yeah.
Ready?
GROUP: Ready.
Suppertime.
[WHIRRING]
[BEEPS]
Hold it.
[BEEPING]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS
OVER MACHINE]
SANDERS:
Congratulations, crew.
You've worked together.
Now feast your eyes on
the wonders of the cosmos.
[♪♪♪]
TROY [OVER RADIO]:
Greendale? Greendale?
Everybody, be quiet. Everybody,
quiet down, quiet down.
Say again?
TROY: Standby for location.
[♪♪♪]
[MOOS]
What do you see, gang?
We are in
Coldwater.
[♪♪♪]
Here, they're next to the
truck stop with three thumbs.
Those aren't thumbs.
JEFF:
Greendale, do you copy?
Greendale?
I'm sorry, Jeff.
I'm afraid
you're out of town.
[MOOS]
[COWS MOOING]
I guess somebody will
come get us eventually.
I really miss Greendale.
How many schools would let you
make a butt flag,
then actually fly it?
How many schools would
let you get a degree
in Theoretical Phys-Ed?
Annie.
We owe you an apology.
Nobody should have to choose
between their friends
and their school.
Thanks.
You shouldn't have tattled
about the flag.
I tattled.
I told the dean
it was our design.
And I told him
it was a butt too.
What?
Why, Jeffrey?
He kept not seeing it.
I mean,
it was driving me crazy.
It says, "E Pluribus Anus."
We should've put
cheeks on it.
There is a time and
a place for subtlety
and that time
was before Scary Movie.
PIERCE:
Hey, guys.
I'm feeling
a lot better now.
You sound good.
In a weird way, being in
a smaller place like this,
I was able to work through
some things.
I think I'm ready
to come out.
I'll kill you.
I will kill you, Sanders.
Come on, man, come on.
[ALL YELLING]
[SANDERS VOICE BREAKING UP]
Get off my mommy.
I'm her man.
SHIRLEY: Pierce.
ANNIE: Stop it.
No, calm down,
Pierce, calm down.
[♪♪♪]
Hey, who's feeling skinny?
Dean, the press is here.
I tried to buy us some time
with these sandwiches,
but they thought I was doing
product integration for KFC.
This Hawaiian bread,
so good, though.
Time to face the music.
MAN:
Craig.
Stephen, surprised
to see you here.
You don't think I'd miss your
moment of triumph, do you?
Greendale beating City College
into simulated space.
Unless you're having trouble
locating your ship.
You.
You were behind this?
The next time you provoke
City College,
you will lose
more than a Winnebago.
JEFF [OVER RADIO]:
Greendale, come in, Greendale.
Go ahead, Kentucky.
You can call off the rescue.
We're coming to save you.
[♪♪♪]
Come on, you family-sized
bucket of bolts.
[♪♪♪]
Abed, construction
on Spring Road.
I see it.
Left on Apple Valley.
Annie, left on Apple.
Hold tight.
[GRUNTING]
Hi.
Get off of me.
They'll never make it back,
Craig.
That thing might as well be
on a simulation of the moon.
Oh, you know what--?
[HORN HONKING
AND TIRES SCREECHING]
Ah! Yes.
[HORN HONKING]
Hey, wait up.
[CHATTERING]
[SCREAMING]
PIERCE:
No.
Ladies and gentlemen, returning
from their maiden simulation,
the fabulous
Greendale Green-stronauts.
[CROWD CHEERING
&amp; APPLAUDING]
Yes.
MAN:
Yeah, that's good.
I picked the team.
I picked this team.
Well, Anne, I suppose you're not
City College material after all.
Thank you.
Annie, that was great.
Good job.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Great job up there, captain.
Really?
Think I could be
a real astronaut?
If NASA ever needs someone
to keep an arrow
inside a moving rectangle,
I know who I'd recommend.
Abed, wanna take a seat
in the captain's chair?
I think you've earned it.
No, thanks.
Can't imagine what
could have been cooler
than what I've done today.
[EXPLOSION]
Okay, that was cooler.
[♪♪♪]
ANNOUNCER:
In the future...
Mission Control,
headed for base.
Target acquired.
ANNOUNCER:
Two cardboard boxes--
I got a bogey on my six.
Yeah, I'm on your six.
Evasive maneuvers.
--are about to become--
Still on your six.
I took evasive maneuvers,
you can't be.
Then I'm on your 12.
That means I'm on your six.
Good.
--space ships.