This is what happened.
We was camping.
We was eating.
And it was mountain lion
jumped down and eat my leg.
I think a mountain lion
jumped down
and eat
someone's grammar. Right?
The auto-tune remix
is better.
Go to related videos.
Uh-huh.
[AUTO-TUNED SINGING]
DUNCAN:
Good.
Professor?
Oh, Annie.
Don't start,
we've been through this.
Anthropology
is the study of humanity,
nothing
is off-topic.
No, it's just,
I've seen this one.
Put in "Car Crash Camel Toe."
Oh, wait, wait, wait,
"Ski Lift Ninja Crotch Rip."
DUNCAN:
Crotch Rip.
MAN:
I'm a ski lift ninja.
CLASS:
Oh!
[STUDENTS CHATTERING]
PIERCE:
Look, Dolly Parton
eating a hot dog.
Stop that.
Yeah.
I can do what I want.
What happens
if you type in "God"?
[STUDENTS BOOING]
Everyone hates you and asks--
Do not boo her.
This subject's lack
of definition cuts both ways.
If farts are fair game,
so is God.
Top hit,
"God of Farts."
Yeah.
DUNCAN: You asked for it.
TROY: It balances out.
[FART SOUND]
That's blasphemous.
Who wants to see that?
Seventeen million people.
Oh.
There were nine people
at my church last night.
Auto-tune "God of Farts."
Yes.
Way ahead of you.
[FART SOUND AUTO-TUNE
REMIXED TO TECHNO MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKER]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Abed?
Guess who's got
two thumbs
and has a career opportunity
for you?
This guy.
I'm pointing my thumbs
at God.
One thumb to say,
"That's great."
I told my pastor about YouTube
and how there's no light there.
Our church wants to sponsor
the making of a video
with a Christian message.
Ha.
What, "Rapping Jesus"?
Please step aside and
make room for a new generation.
Abed, would you like to make
a Christian YouTube?
You're Muslim--
As a Muslim, I'd be happy to.
As a filmmaker, no. I'm a
storyteller, not a preacher.
The Bible has been called
the greatest story ever told.
Ben Lyons said the same thing
about I Am Legend.
Oh, well, I'll have
to rent that then.
Whoa.
What?
That's a lot of pasta
for no veggies.
You're not in charge
of what I eat.
True. Britta.
And some damn broccoli,
please.
Pierce has been acting out
a lot lately,
maybe you should talk
to him.
How is that my job?
Aren't you, like,
the dad?
Would the dad walk away
from this conversation?
No? Uh--
You're having cookies for lunch?
Yeah.
Hey, you didn't pay for those.
Call a cop.
Heads up, gay wads.
Oh, yummy.
They're better
when they're free.
Fresh and stolen.
What are you looking at?
Your face.
That's what you're supposed
to look at.
So?
So you gonna sit down or what?
Oh, no, I usually sit
with the younger people.
Well, la di da di da.
No, no, we watch videos
on YouTune,
and you guys
don't know what that is.
We don't care.
Pierce, looking for us?
We're sitting over there.
I can see.
Sheesh.
Did you take your pills?
Ooh.
Meet Mama's boy.
We're having
a private conversation here.
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
Hi, I'm Britta. Pierce's--
Pbbt!
Very nice
meeting you guys.
[CHUCKLES]
[MIMICS BRITTA]
"Very nice meeting you guys."
[ALL LAUGH]
She's a lesbian.
Come on.
[♪♪♪]
Shirley, I read
the New Testament.
The whole thing?
Being raised by TV and movies,
I thought Jesus walked on water
and told people not to have
abortions, but it's cooler.
He was like E.T.,
Edward Scissorhands
and Marty McFly combined.
I'd love to make
a Jesus movie.
Abed, that's wonderful.
What do you think we should do?
Needs to be cool
and addictive.
Like that video
of the kitten falling asleep.
The story's been told
to death,
I wanna approach it
in a new way.
We need a Jesus movie
for the post post-modern world.
Like Jesus as a rapper?
No. I wanna tell
the story of Jesus
from the perspective
of a filmmaker
exploring the life
of Jesus.
That sounds very appealing
to filmmakers.
In the film,
Jesus is a filmmaker
trying to find God
with his camera.
He realizes
that he's Jesus
and he's being
filmed by God's camera.
It goes like that forever
because the filmmakers are Jesus
and the cameras are God.
And the movie is called,
ABED.
All caps.
Filmmaking beyond film.
A meta film.
My masterpiece.
I don't like it.
It's okay. You're reacting
the way the world did to Jesus.
I'm reacting the way
the world does
to movies
about making movies
about making movies.
Come on, Charlie Kaufman,
some of us have work
in the morning.
You don't wanna work
on the movie?
This means there is no movie.
[♪♪♪]
This is the movie.
The game
is Jacks and Deuces wild.
Except if the dean comes in
and then it's Bingo.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Keep it, I got another one.
If you get caught
with that,
just say
it's your 90th birthday.
Suddenly,
it's adorable.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
All right.
All right now.
What is this again?
B-19.
No, B-19 my butt,
I told you guys, no poker.
All right, shut this down.
Shut your mouth down,
fruit.
Oh, hey,
unacceptable.
None of your business,
and barely the truth.
All right,
everyone, go home.
Excuse me, mister?
What, Pierce?
What year is it?
What?
Poker helps him remember.
Veronica.
[SOFTLY]
Okay.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[♪♪♪]
You're okay, kid.
Shut up and deal,
let's go.
Jesus, did you really die
for our sins? That's dopey.
Oh, uh-- Dope.
Oh, Freudian slip.
Perhaps due to my feeling dopey.
Do the line, atheist.
[ANGRILY]
Jesus, did you really die
for our sins?
That's dope.
If you think that's dope,
check out these
"beat-titudes."
[CHUCKLES]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS
OVER KEYBOARD]
♪ Blessed be the peacemaker's
Word to the meek ♪
♪ The kingdom of Heaven
Is open all week ♪
♪ Jesus and me-- ♪♪
[EXPLOSION]
ABED:
I have arrived.
I am watched as I am watching.
I am audience and creation.
[♪♪♪]
The Earth shall know my power.
Abed,
what are you doing?
Oh, great.
You blew the take.
No, no, keep rolling.
This can all be part of it.
CROWD: Ahh...
ABED:
There are no takes.
There is no viewer.
The film is the story,
the story is us.
We are the film.
This is totally meta.
Let's get back to our
non-meta production, shall we?
Come on.
No, I wanna watch this.
Troy,
there's no time.
Then we quit.
Right, Britta?
I don't even believe in God,
but I love me some Abed.
Yeah.
What are you--?
But...
[♪♪♪]
STUDENT:
Oh, look at it.
"The story of the story
is the story."
Sure, that'll play
in Poughkeepsie.
I heard some theaters
are gonna show it in reverse.
I heard it's the same movie
backward and forward.
I heard the deleted scenes
are the scenes
and the scenes
are the deleted scenes.
I heard Jesus died
for our sins.
Wait, guys.
The director's answering
questions in the cafeteria.
And it both is
and isn't part of the movie.
Yes.
Get a table.
[♪♪♪]
Abed, are we all
in the movie right now?
We are all in a movie
even when there are no cameras.
When will the movie
be released?
When is life released?
Every minute
is a world premiere.
My father has already bought
the popcorn.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Excuse me, Abed?
But you aren't
actually trying to say
that you're Jesus,
are you?
I am who you say I am.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Okay, yeah. Whoo.
It's meta now.
Except here is a thing:
I am a devout Christian,
and you guys are feeding
into this poor boy's delusions.
So cool. She's an actual,
real-life Pharisee.
Hey, bitch, why don't you
go back to your temple?
STUDENT 1: Yeah.
STUDENT 2: Yeah.
Why don't you all stop
confusing Jesus
with an egotistical,
filmmaking lunatic?
[CROWD GASPS]
I forgive her.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
So how's
your film going, Abed?
Blasphemously.
It's not blasphemy to say
that we are God, Shirley.
First Corinthians:
He who unites himself
with the Lord
is one with him
in spirit.
Did you just scripture me,
Muslim?
Jesus was Jewish.
Are you ever gonna let that go?
JEFF: Hey.
No religious talk.
Somebody's late.
What is that
in your pocket?
Jeff, Britta,
Pierce is smoking cigars.
What's it to you, butt breath?
Oh.
Look at your eyes. Out all night
with those hipsters?
Hipsters?
Pack of old people
in the cafeteria.
"Hipsters" because they have
hip replacements.
They do not.
Leonard will probably
kick your ass.
Leonard?
You're hanging out
with Leonard?
You know I hate him.
So?
Everybody hates him.
That's why he's cool.
You people
don't get it.
I'm not sure
that I want to get it.
Take a break from these
new friends of yours.
They've got you all riled up.
That's what Leonard
said you'd say.
JEFF:
Leonard is not a part
of this study group.
So you apologize
right now to-- What?
I'm not your father.
I never said you were.
Where are you going?
Out.
Uh-- When did Pierce
become awesome?
I'm gonna
shut you down, know that?
I do.
I'm supposed
to shut you down.
I'm not gonna do it.
Don't.
I won't.
Good.
I am gonna shut you down.
[♪♪♪]
You should have seen
his face.
He was terrified.
You're his worst
nightmare now.
You're old
and you don't give a damn.
Boo-yah! Ha-ha.
[SHIRLEY INHALES DEEPLY]
Don't make eye contact,
we'll be fine.
Okay.
Silly old wuss.
LEONARD: Hey--
JOE: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The dude is got a date.
Little lovely.
Please give us a break?
JOE: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Don't wanna see you
when I come back.
Go, run.
We've made them angry.
He left his keys.
Oh, who's up
for a joy ride?
I don't know. We could get
into serious trouble.
Oh, come on.
If we get caught, we can just
pretend we're disoriented,
they can give us
a ride home.
Where am I?
What year is it?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
But we've all been drinking.
Oh, grow a schmekel.
[HIPSTERS LAUGHING]
Okay, everyone,
this is the last scene.
I wanna thank you all
for contributing
to the greatest film
ever made.
And on the seventh day,
Shirley shut down production.
Abed, Shirley has informed me
you are using school equipment
on school property
to make a religious film.
She has filed
an official complaint,
invoking the separation
of church and state.
Pointed out the irony to her.
Don't give a crap.
Let's be ironic,
shut it down.
Abed, are you making
a religious film?
All movies
are religious to me.
Nice.
But is it a movie
about Jesus?
Is The Matrix?
Is RoboCop?
Is Superman Returns?
All stories are about death
and resurrection.
I've got one, Wrath of Khan.
That's a good one.
Spock sacrifices himself
for the crew and gets reborn.
How captivating was Ricardo
Montalban in that? I'm serious--
Except in Abed's film, the
character's name isn't Spock.
That's true. It's Abed.
Oh. I'm getting
creative goosebumps here.
I love Charlie Kaufman.
ABED:
I need to run into editing,
grab a chair
and you can watch a take.
[♪♪♪]
I would love that.
I've never watched a take
before. This is exciting.
Uh-- You...
Say what you will about Abed,
but the man cannot be killed.
[CHUCKLES]
I mean, it's almost like
he's Jesus.
I got it.
I don't think
we should be driving,
I mean, we're all,
you know, old and groggy.
Ah. Stop worrying.
Richard flew zeroes
during the Big One.
What do you mean "flew zeroes"?
He's not Japanese.
What did you fly
during the Big One, Rich?
Where am I?
Oh, stop farting around.
Seriously, I don't know
where I am.
What year is it?
How do I drive?
[ALL YELLING]
Hey, give me it.
PIERCE:
Look out, look out.
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
Let's bail.
Wait a minute,
what about Richard?
Screw Richard,
it's every man for himself.
I'm getting out of here.
Richard,
are you all right?
Well...
Am I Richard?
Yes.
Then I'm fine.
But who are those people
that ran away?
Our friends?
That's a good question.
Oh.
[♪♪♪]
What is?
ABED [OVER MONITOR]:
There are no takes.
There is no viewer.
The film is the story,
the story is us.
We are the film.
So, what do you think?
I need to take a walk.
[INSECTS CHIRPING]
Dear God. My movie
is the worst piece of crap
I have ever seen
in my entire life.
How could I have been
so blind?
It's a self-indulgent,
adolescent mess.
I can barely sit through it.
And now with all this hype,
I've got a real
Snakes on a Plane brewing.
Critics are gonna crucify me,
my career will be over
before it begins.
God, if you're out there,
I know I don't deserve it,
but I need your help.
Please take this project
away from me.
Make it rain.
Send a meteor.
Anything. Please?
Now?
Okay, I get it.
This is what I deserve.
I'll finish it up.
[♪♪♪]
[ELECTRICITY POWERING DOWN]
Hi. I'm Pierce Hawthorne's
emergency contact.
Here to pick him up?
No.
I'm here to be removed
as his emergency contact.
One second.
LEONARD: Hey.
I've got a class.
Does anybody have--?
Where is everybody?
Is anyone coming
to get Leonard?
No, nobody comes
for him anymore.
His kids asked us
to stop calling them.
Why do you think
he acts like that?
[♪♪♪]
RICHARD:
So we're in prison, right?
All right,
bring him out.
Come here, Pierce.
Up, up.
Ahem. Hey.
Go wait in the car.
It wasn't my fault.
[LAUGHS]
You want me to change that
or not?
I guess not.
Could you do me a favor?
Could you add Britta Perry
as a contact?
P-E-R-R-Y.
Give her a call
a couple times a week?
She gets pretty worried
about him.
And she works days,
so make sure you call at night.
[♪♪♪]
Everyone thinks what you did
was destined to happen.
That it was proof
God was making my movie.
A movie so good
it could never exist.
They think I'm a genius,
and they think you're a villain.
Hmm.
You heard me praying.
I don't know what you mean.
Oh, this is gonna be good.
Abed sent me a new link
and that man knows
his video virality.
So you're just gonna drop
all pretense
of actually teaching us?
Yeah. Here we go.
♪ Blessed be the peacemaker's
Word to the meek ♪
♪ The kingdom of Heaven
Is open all week ♪
You finished my movie.
Don't know what you mean.
♪ Only from
The saint there ♪
♪ Lepers have feet there
Dogs love cats there ♪
♪ Cats love mice ♪
You humble me.
You humble me too.
♪ And the tables are pies ♪
♪ Ice cream is everywhere
But never on your thighs ♪
♪ Good news is
It can be your hood ♪
Okay, open your books because
Abed has broken the Internet.
♪ As in word of God, yo ♪♪
[CHUCKLES]
[IN UNISON]
Great.
So which one of us
is gonna head home and...
BOTH:
Change.
[HUMMING]
ALL:
Hilarious.
So you guys bought one
of my outfits,
and then staked out my apartment
every day until I wore it?
That's not pathetic.
Okay.
Well,
good job.
I guess I'm heading home
to change now.
I hit traffic,
did I miss it?
ALL:
Darn it.