NARRATOR:
Halloween:
A time of vampires,
hobgoblins, Draculas,
boogens
and headless mice.
I'm George Takei.
You know what?
Let's just get to it.
[ABBA'S "WATERLOO"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
How is it?
Pretty good taco meat.
I wonder how the dean
scored this sweet spread.
Ah-ah-ah. Chef Gaga
never reveals her caterer.
And don't try reading
my pa- pa- pa- poker face.
It's military rations
from an Army surplus store.
I didn't read
your poker face,
you left the containers
in the garbage.
Oh, well, um,
you guys have fun.
I'm gonna go
take out the garbage.
You may also want to
adjust your iTunes setting.
When it's not playing
an endless loop of
ABBA's greatest hits,
it's playing what may be
your personal voice memos.
What?
PELTON:
Note to self: Get oil changed.
Check Netflix
for that movie
where Greg Kinnear
plays a ghost.
No, an angel.
And something called
Human Centi--
[ABBA'S "WATERLOO"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
David Beckham.
Dragon turtle?
T-Rex.
Man, I wonder how
much effort you put
into being
accidentally handsome
for a costume every year.
Half the effort
you'll be putting
into eating and drinking.
Let me help you,
dragon turtle.
Guys, Shirley's costume
is once again
unwittingly ambiguous.
I don't know
what she's supposed to be,
but I do know
she's not Miss Piggy.
I repeat,
she is not Miss Piggy.
You're on your own.
Hello.
Guess who I am.
Umm. Can't you just say?
No.
[GROANING]
Pierce, are you okay?
Huh? What?
Whoa. Hey, if you get
any more sweaty and puffy,
your costume's
gonna reach authenticity.
Oh, I don't understand.
Shut up.
He's acting like
the impression of him we do.
"What?"
"Where am I?"
"Where's the black boy
in the uniform?"
PIERCE:
Leave me alone.
Get away from me!
Oh, man, just when
you think it's funny.
ANNIE: Pierce?
You know something?
Okay, okay. Okay.
Excuse me, I think
my friend is really sick.
I'm not a doctor.
I'm a doctor.
Annie.
Rich, from pottery class.
Oh, hey.
Wow, this looks serious.
Let's get him over here.
ANNIE: Okay.
RICH:
Boy, he is just not
in very good shape, is he?
But you look fantastic.
Oh, thank you.
RICH:
Look at you, with your hood.
[♪♪♪]
[HISSING]
Right, between--
Oh, my God.
What is it?
Get away from those hotties.
[♪♪♪]
[IMITATES MACHINE-GUN FIRE]
[WOMEN GROAN]
You're safe now.
If that thing comes back,
I need one or both
of your phone numbers.
Yeah, right.
[IMITATES ROBOTIC
MACHINERY WHIRRING]
I don't get it.
How do you do it?
Well, I'm wearing
a $6,000 suit,
and you spent three days
making cardboard robot armor.
Saying they feel sorry for you?
I'm saying I remind girls
less of taking their little
brothers to Comic-Con.
PELTON: Rich.
More?
Put her with the others.
Hundred and two.
This may be food poisoning.
Rich, what did I tell you?
To rule out food poisoning.
Yes.
But also not to
say the words out loud.
Who wants to walk
my plank, huh? Hey.
[SCREAMING]
Okay, I'm ruling out
food poisoning.
[SCREAMING]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
[DOG HOWLING]
[ABBA'S "S.O.S"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Guess who I am.
Michelle Kwan?
Wrong.
Kristi Yamaguchi?
Peggy Fleming.
Just been proven racist
by the racist prover.
Hey, guess who I am.
Drink.
Have you noticed a weird vibe
taking hold of this party?
It's like
every fifth person
is on something
seriously hard-core.
Yeah, I wonder
who's holding
the key to your riddle.
Hey.
Where's your costume?
I'm trying something new.
But our costumes
go together.
And if you're not in yours,
I'm a guy in a spandex suit
and a helmet.
Well, I'm a sexy Dracula.
You mean vampire.
I don't need to know
which Dracula I am
to be a Dracula.
Nerd.
Your symptoms
are progressing even faster
than everyone else's.
How much of that taco meat
did you eat?
I didn't eat any.
My name is Alex.
Must have transferred
through Pierce's bite.
My God, I think you're right.
Annie, you make
quite the little nurse.
Thank you, Rich.
You're quite a banana.
STAR-BURNS:
Jeez, why don't you guys
just get a--?
[GROWLING]
[ANNIE SCREAMING]
But the only people getting sick
are the ones eating
what I bought
at your surplus store.
MAN 1:
I never said
the stuff was delicious,
but you can't get sick,
it's non-perishable.
What about the taco meat stuff?
The what?
The classic flavor?
Huh?
The one with the goofy label.
Here.
What goofy label?
What are you--?
"Classified Phoenix.
"If found,
repeat key phrase,
echo, tango, x-ray,
nine, nine, seven."
Yeah, sounds delicious.
Anyway, it looks like
taco meat and--
[STATIC CRACKLES OVER PHONE]
Hello?
MAN 2:
Greendale Community College?
Speaking.
This is Special Operations
Officer McHenry.
Hi.
I need you to listen to me
very carefully.
[ABBA'S "DANCING QUEEN"
PLAYING]
Okay, one hint.
I'm a beloved character
from our childhood.
I can't stop seeing it.
I know.
[GROWLING]
Leonard, behave.
I'm a Christian woman.
Leonard, you better
back that pumpkin ass up
or I will make a pie.
Hey, Jeff. It's me, Rich,
from pottery class.
Doc Potterywood, remember?
Rich, bigger fish.
There's an infection
at the party
making people act weird
and bite each other.
We need to coordinate
an evacuation
without causing
unnecessary panic.
[SCREAMING]
Holy crap,
Leonard's a zombie.
Zombie attack!
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Never mind.
Oh, my God.
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Um. Um!
I'm sorry.
Open the door!
I've been told we need
a little baby quarantine
until the Army gets here.
ALL: The Army?
I know, right?
They said to wait for six hours.
Stay strong.
Guys, I hate to be the
"we've got company" guy, but...
Hey, guess who I am.
Or don't.
Head to the back!
[SCREAMING]
[GROWLING AND SCREAMING]
You punched a lady bee.
JEFF:
Let go of the door,
you little bitch.
CHANG:
Welcome.
Oh, thank God you're all right.
JEFF: Shirley, door.
CHANG:
Oh, he did it.
Okay, did we lose anybody there?
ANNIE: No.
JEFF: Is anybody hurt?
No.
Last question,
and I know it's a long shot.
Did anybody shut off
the dean's playlist?
PELTON:
Two percent milk, eggs,
deodorant, Puppy Chow,
black light, whole milk...
Okay.
Cotton swabs.
It's officially
a waking nightmare.
Add Eat Pray Love soundtrack
to workout mix.
When are the police coming?
WOMAN: Help is on the way.
Hello?
Help is on the way. Help--
Flavor Flav was right.
It's the end of days.
It can't be the end of days.
It's not 2012 yet.
It's not the end of days.
It's a rabies-related pathogen
affecting the prefrontal cortex
of the brain,
causing hyperaggression.
It could take years
to take over the world.
How many years?
One, one and a half.
2012, end of days.
End of days, end of days.
Good thinking, Jeff,
vertical fold.
You making fun of me?
That jacket is worth more
than the island you were
grown on, Chiquita MD.
Chiquita MD, I like it.
This is a good time
to let you know I hate you.
Shouldn't we be
barricading the room?
I don't know.
These guys don't seem so--
I will help you.
Wait, before you
barricade us in,
I need to ask
if anyone has been bitten.
You bit? Huh?
You bit?
This pathogen
is spread through bites.
If anyone has been bitten
and you allow us to seal
ourselves in here with you,
you're putting us all
in danger.
All right, go ahead.
ABED:
Nice. Okay, I got the middle.
Barricade.
BRITTA:
Are we really
just gonna sit here?
Army's gonna be here
in six hours.
Why six hours?
Are they hosting the Oscars?
Damn. And the winner
for Best Adapted Oscar Burn:
Jeff Winger for Oh, Snap:
The Man Who Went There.
They don't have six hours.
Judging from the temperatures,
in three hours, they're
gonna suffer brain damage.
After that,
they're gonna be dead.
What? We have to do
something for them.
Do something
for the zombies?
If we lower the temperature
of the building,
would it break the fever
and kill the virus?
It might.
I know where the thermostat is,
out on the wall.
Troy, we have to
rise to the occasion
like Ripley and kick butt.
I'm not Ripley, Abed.
I'm a cool, sexy Dracula.
I make love to ladies
and I survive.
I'm with Troy.
Guys, those are not zombies.
Those are our classmates
and they're sick.
They can make us sick
by biting us.
The banana said so.
It's true.
The incubation
only takes minutes.
You get a stomach ache,
then your skin turns red.
Followed by cold sweats,
muscle spasms, high fever.
Then the uncontrollable urge
to bite uninfected flesh.
Oh, Jesus.
And I forgot one symptom.
Slurred speech.
[SCREAMING]
You got bit!
I felt like maybe I was special.
Special?
You're not special.
I'm special.
I was bit 10 minutes ago
and I'm f--
Oh, great.
Nobody's special!
Hey, Rich, just so you know,
I hate you less now.
That's how much
I hate your normal self.
You have to destroy the brain.
[ANNIE SCREAMING]
Hamster!
A hamster!
Way to go. Run, run!
[ABBA'S "GIMME! GIMME! GIMME!
(A MAN AFTER MIDNIGHT)"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
JEFF: Head for the stairs!
CHANG: Look out.
SHIRLEY:
What about Annie?
JEFF: Don't look back.
Why not? Oh!
CHANG:
Shirley.
Don't look back.
[GROANING AND SCREAMING]
ABED:
We have to go help them.
JEFF:
You can't help them
by getting bit.
CHANG:
It's occupied.
Occupied.
Oh, this is how I die,
as Miss Piggy.
You're not Miss Piggy.
You're Glinda the Good Witch.
You knew?
Just so you know,
I've always loved Peggy Fleming.
You're not a racist.
Mm-mm.
[♪♪♪]
Mm? Mm.
JEFF:
Get in. Get in.
Oh, cool.
A dark basement.
I was just thinking
we should be doing this
in a dark basement.
Troy, why did you
ditch your costume?
Why bring that up now, Abed?
We might die down here.
All the more reason
to get this ironed out.
You called me a nerd.
What defines a nerd?
Committing to a costume
with your best friend,
is that what nerds do?
I don't know,
because I'm not a nerd,
so I'm not taking part
in this conversation.
[CLATTERING]
Shh! Nerds!
Did you hear that?
[CAT SCREECHES]
Jeez!
[LAUGHS]
It was just a cat.
Let's keep moving.
[CAT SCREECHES]
Holy crap.
What is up with that cat?
Is someone throwing it?
ABED: Let's keep moving.
Let's not keep moving,
because there is an insane cat
down here.
But what about
the zombies?
Back burner, Troy.
This cat has to be dealt with.
[CAT SCREECHES]
There it is, grab it!
ABED: Get him.
Let's go through there.
Door should lead upstairs,
the thermostat--
Enough with
the thermostat, Abed.
This is not "pretend playtime,
save the world" time.
It's quarter past
"let's get the hell
out of this building" time.
There.
There's a window.
If we climb that fence,
we can hoist Troy
against the wall
and then squeeze through it.
I vote we take the door.
He doesn't wanna
dirty his suit.
For real?
Clothes make the man, Troy.
What the--? Hey!
[♪♪♪]
[JEFF SCREAMING]
That's my jacket.
My jacket, you're stretching it.
You're stretching it!
TROY:
Go back, go back, go back.
ABED:
Don't stop. Keep going.
Move, move!
Now drop down, drop down.
To the gate, to the gate.
Go.
I'm not going without you.
Troy, make me proud.
Be the first black man
to make it to the end.
Go, go, go.
Abed.
I love you.
I know.
[♪♪♪]
No!
Ah! Okay. Troy, be honest.
Are you a zombie?
I will mace you.
Give me the keys.
People are gonna get brain
damage if someone doesn't help.
Troy, there is something
called chain of command,
so unfortunately--
No.
Are you crazy?
How are you gonna
survive those zombies?
I'm gonna be a nerd.
Better have a plan B.
[ABBA'S "MAMMA MIA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[IMITATES ROBOTIC
MACHINERY WHIRRING]
That's right.
Prepare to meet
the power of imagination.
Okay, I don't know why
I thought this would work.
Hey, get off me! Get off.
You're so strong.
God, I hate this! Get off.
Stop using your mouth.
Hello, zombie Annie.
What big fists you have,
in your face.
Beam this up, Scotty.
In your face.
Zombie Shirley.
I don't know what you are,
but in your face!
Abed, we're friends.
Abed, no! Ah! Britta.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, okay.
I've been bit, y'all.
Damn. Congrats.
You did what zombies do.
[♪♪♪]
Jeff.
Still cool as a zombie.
[GROANS]
[GROWLS]
[ABBA'S "FERNANDO"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ We were young
And full of life ♪
♪ And none of us
Prepared to die ♪
♪ And I'm not ashamed to say ♪
♪ The roar of guns
And cannons ♪
♪ Almost made me cry ♪
♪ There was something
In the air that night ♪
♪ The stars were bright,
Fernando ♪
♪ They were shining there
For you and me ♪
♪ For liberty, Fernando ♪
♪ Though we never thought
That we could lose ♪
♪ There's no regret ♪
Out of the way, out of the way,
out of the way!
MAN 1: Lock down perimeter!
MAN 2: We got movement inside.
You're Dean Pelton?
PELTON: Speaking.
Wow, six hours on the dot.
Yeah, well,
practice makes perfect.
You the only witness?
I am.
All right.
MAN 3:
Hey, we got uninfected in here.
How many are we talking?
MAN 3:
Think it might be all of them.
All right, scenario B.
Repeat, scenario B.
Let's dose these suckers.
Dose what now?
MAN 3:
Going in.
MAN 4:
Go to scenario B.
[SPRAYING GAS]
ABED:
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't remember anything.
It's not bad, right?
ANNIE: There you go.
You remember nothing past
your decision to be Lady Gaga?
I can't believe
that somebody would
mass-roofie
an entire party.
I can't believe it wasn't me.
I can't believe I believe you.
And I don't.
Wanna watch a movie?
Sure. Aliens,
cyborgs or zombies?
I don't know why,
but I'm kind of over zombies.
Yeah, I don't feel
like anything action-heavy.
How about something light?
You seen Marmaduke?
NARRATOR:
And so Troy and Abed
went back to the dormitory
for a viewing of Marmaduke.
I'm George Takei.
And if your name is Kevin,
here's a little freebie
for your cell phone.
Hi, Kevin can't come
to the phone.
He's on a spaceship with me,
George Takei.
Please leave a message.
You're welcome, Kevins.
Happy Halloween.
Voice mail.
WOMAN [ON RECORDING]:
October 31st, 11:20 p.m.
CHANG [ON RECORDING]:
Troy, this is Chang.
There's not much time.
I don't think
we're gonna make it.
Listen, if you survive,
please spread this message
for me:
Shirley and I
totally did it.
SHIRLEY:
Chang, what are you doing?
CHANG:
Nothing.
[SHIRLEY SCREAMING ON RECORDING]
Gotta go.
Why did he call me?