[HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING]
Ready for the Bus Driver,
Winger?
Know why they call me
Bus Driver?
You've been traveling?
Because I'm taking
your butt to school.
Nice.
Heh, heh.
Cool, I'm up.
No, game's to 15.
Since when?
Since you scored 11.
Sorry, Abed, I have to finish
kicking Troy's butt.
All that angry talk
about butts.
Kick your butt, stomp your butt,
punch your butt.
Do they say "punch your butt"?
Point is,
hatred of each other's butts.
Men play sports
so they can seek out
and destroy
their own sensitivity.
Oh, I never thought about it
that way.
Mm-hm.
Think we'll learn that
in our women's studies class?
Hell, no. We're gonna find
our roots in that class
and stop defining
our gender by theirs.
Well, I feel bad saying it,
but it will be nice
to get away from the boys
and take a class with just us.
Amen.
Or a-women.
Am I right?
Bring it in
for a boob bump, ladies.
SHIRLEY: Uh...
No? We'll get there.
Hey, guys.
Remember when you played with
those remote control cars
and you thought
you were real cool?
Well, it turns out you're not.
DraganFlyer, beyotch.
Yep, four propellers.
It's got a built-in spy cam.
Range, 100 yards,
and it will strangle
your stupid cars' little butts.
Pierce, we're in a game.
Yeah.
And we're really not
into RC anymore.
What?
But that's a DraganFlyer.
Come on, Pierce.
JEFF: Pierce.
I can't control it.
There's a little pilot in there.
Whoa!
Stop it.
[WOMEN SCREAM]
Knuckle walkers.
Sorry, it was an accident.
So was the Y chromosome,
but you don't see us
throwing stuff at it.
[CHUCKLES]
Where are you guys going?
Away from your symbolically
invasive balls
to a women's studies class.
Which women's class?
Feminist Representations
in Media.
I'm in.
Abed, we kind of thought
this would be something
just for the girls.
Sounds like it. I'd love
to learn more about you.
I'll change out of my sport
clothes and meet you there.
Um...
♪ You just lost ♪
♪ You just lost a game ♪
♪ With Troy ♪
Hey, sore loser.
Yeah, proud of it.
I want a rematch.
[GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Hey, guys. I raced here
so I could save us four seats.
Thanks, Abed,
but Annie can't see the board
from this far back.
She lost her glasses.
I've never seen you
wear glasses.
I wear contacts,
but I couldn't find them
without glasses,
which I wear.
Cool, cool, cool.
Are we bad people?
No, I love Abed, but sometimes
he can't take a hint.
We told him,
this is a girl thing.
Ahem.
Excuse me,
we were gonna sit there.
Oh, sorry, we didn't know, but
now we're sitting here, so...
That's the problem.
You don't seriously
expect us to get up
and change seats for you.
Well, if you're
further in back,
less people
will see your roots.
Um, excuse me?
Oh, the way you excuse
your little mustache hairs?
You know what?
We're good people,
so we will find seats
elsewhere.
It's called the high road.
I hope it leads to a salon.
ALL:
Oh!
You're back.
The leader's name is Meghan.
Why name your daughter
Meghan?
Are you stocking up
for a bitch shortage?
The one with the hole
in her sweater's armpit?
Or whose sleeves are pushing
her fat toward her elbows?
No, those are her cronies.
The one with crooked ears
and no ankles?
Ha. Damn.
Sorry, I overdescribed again?
No, no, Abed.
Describe those girls
all you want.
In fact,
what are you doing for lunch?
It's Wednesday.
Sometimes I eat in Jeff's car.
Don't tell him.
Troy, where are you?
You would go this far
to avoid a rematch?
[♪♪♪]
Jeff, what is this thing?
In my line of work?
A multimillion-dollar
injury suit.
I thought schools
got rid of these things.
I can't believe
Greendale allows it.
JOSHUA:
Greendale doesn't.
That's why it's hidden.
Who else saw you come in?
If we say nobody,
are you going to stab us
with your bush scissors?
Of course not.
I'm Joshua.
And this is a place of
peace and balance.
A place of nourishment.
A place free from darkness.
Because there's a trampoline?
There is something cool
about being up here, Jeff.
I mean, at first,
I was just jumping, but then--
But then,
you started bouncing.
Like a baby
on the knee of a goddess.
Yes. Yes.
Jeff, get on.
Oh, one at a time, please.
I must ask you to adhere
to two simple principles.
First, for this place to survive
it must stay secret.
Second,
no double bouncies.
JOSHUA:
Feet, shoulder width apart.
Knees bent.
Just breathe.
At the apex of each bounce,
there's a moment
outside of time,
outside of words,
outside of everything.
A perfect moment.
A silent moment.
[♪♪♪]
I call it
the world's whisper.
Wow. You're right.
And I don't mind admitting
you're right.
Which is weird.
Thirty seconds on this thing
and I already feel--
Jeff, you've been up there
for an hour.
[CHUCKLES]
[JEFF &amp; TROY LAUGHING]
Yes.
BRITTA:
Okay, Abed, girl in the pink.
Go.
Her forehead hangs
over her head like a canopy.
Missed a belt loop. Her stomach
spills over her shorts.
Target destroyed.
It's called a muffin top, Abed.
Like a muffin.
Clever.
You said it's rude
to focus on imperfections.
This is the stuff
I filter, right?
Absolutely. It's just
kind of a guilty pleasure
to hear it
about certain girls.
Like Meghan and her friends,
because they're bitches.
Oh, hoo-hoo. That's nice.
Who needs a soda?
I'll get it. I'm making you
happy, I wanna keep it going.
WOMEN:
Aw.
Okay, I love Abed so much.
I know, it's like
he's one of the girls.
Uh, guys?
Uh-oh.
Yeah, do you mind
not looking at me?
Do you mind that your face
makeup doesn't match your neck?
When I squint,
you look like a circus clown.
[LAUGHS]
Okay,
I beg your pardon, geek?
I don't even know
your peanut-headed ass.
We've never met. Like your hair
and dandruff shampoo.
Ha, ha, ha. Filet of Meghan.
Service for one.
Okay, Abed,
let's get back to the table.
Yeah, Abed,
go with your skank.
Or keep going, up to you.
About what?
Her uneven bra padding?
You look like you're smuggling
a lime and a coconut.
Go away, loser.
Tell that to the stitching
in your ratty panties. Or wear
higher jeans on laundry day.
Damn.
That dis made me snarf, yo.
You know what,
you're dead?
You're bow-legged.
See you.
BRITTA:
Women of Greendale.
This cafeteria is hereby
declared a Bitch-Free Zone.
[ALL CHEERING]
Whoot, whoot, whoot!
[♪♪♪]
I can't tell you
how great I feel.
I wasn't sure that you would
take to the trampoline's ways.
Some can't.
And some are
just natural jumpers.
See you tomorrow, Joshua.
We better bounce.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Whoa.
That's Sharice. I had sociology
with her last year.
She told me
I walk like a dude.
That's awful.
Abed, got anything?
I might have something to say
about those jeans.
You guys are sure
it's not bad?
Isn't that bad when
you're doing it to bad girls.
You're really good at it.
You're like a machine.
Like RoboCop.
Exactly like Rowboat Cop.
Sharice is a bad rowboat.
Sink her.
Affirmative.
[BLEEPING]
You look like a dude
in those jeans.
They're bad. Bad.
[CRYING]
[♪♪♪]
Hey, you dudes ready to shoot
the rock after study group?
I'm gonna slit
your butts' throats.
Nice catch, losers.
Go get it.
Sorry, Pierce. We're not really
into basketball anymore.
PIERCE:
What?
What's up with you guys?
Why are you acting like that?
Like what?
Ah! Gay boots. Lady boots.
Heh, heh, heh.
He's a gay wad.
Those as comfortable
as they look?
They're like wearing
a pair of dreams.
I'm sure your shoes
are fine, though.
You know what? They are.
Something's up with you two.
I wanna know what it is.
Are you on weed?
Give me some, I'll smoke
you two under the table.
Man, I feel so good.
It's like the campus
is a gutter
and we're spraying it clean.
Abed, I need you to come
to the bank with me
to have words
with a certain something.
We'll take them down. We'll take
all these bitches down.
Ladies, are you okay?
Take it easy.
Um, did you just tell us
what to do?
Here's the thing,
it's a little rule.
Maybe you're not
familiar with it.
Nobody tells me
what to do, ever.
Whoa, cowboy.
I surrender.
Abed,
did you hear that?
Jeff's a bitch too?
Yes.
Take him down.
Cool. Hey, Jeff,
what's with the boots?
2008 called to tell you
that even in 2008,
those were tacky.
You go, girl.
Damn.
Why don't we just all
take a deep breath
and find some center?
Okay, that is it.
What are you hiding from me?
They're keeping
relaxation secrets.
Tell me how to get laid back
or I'll kill your families!
BRITTA:
Okay, this place is lame.
Girls. Abed.
Toodles.
I'm watching you two.
Twenty four, 2010.
These balls,
on your butts.
Quick bounce before lunch?
Absolutely.
Let me just make sure that
Pierce isn't hovering around.
Coast is clear.
[♪♪♪]
What did you see, my pretty?
Wait. Back, back.
Freeze it.
Can you blow that up a little?
Enhance.
Stop. That's it.
Blow it up.
There it is.
Um, excuse me, girls,
you're sitting in our seats.
I'm sorry, what did you say?
Oh, I didn't know
you were deaf.
I suspected you were blind
from the outfit.
[GASPS]
SHIRLEY:
Toodles.
ANNIE:
See you.
Wait, why were you mean to them?
Did they insult you?
No, but that top
insulted our retinas.
[ALL LAUGHING]
BRITTA:
Go, girl.
Bad isn't that bad when
you're doing it to bad girls.
[BEEPING]
Annie, when you laugh like that,
you snort like a piglet.
Careful, Abed.
Be careful with your skin.
Your face is puffy,
your eyes look like buttons.
Check that attitude at the door.
Check the door before
you go through it.
What? What?
Abed, you cannot
talk to us that way.
Someone has to.
You guys are being bitches.
We're not bitches.
We were just joking.
If that makes us bitches,
we're all bitches.
Mm-hm. Good point, Annie.
Mm-hm. You told him.
Affirmative.
You're all bitches.
Nice shirt.
It would look better on a girl.
You're not fooling us
with that Band-Aid, it's a zit.
You're all bitches.
Triple bitches.
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
Hey, bitch.
Bitch. You're a bitch.
I'm a bitch. You're a bitch.
[♪♪♪]
[RUSTLING]
Pierce.
Ha, ha.
How did you find us?
DraganFlyer, beyotch.
So this is the big secret, huh?
You two sneak out here and hang
out on the big gay trampoline.
Lower your voice, Pierce.
This is our place of peace.
Yes, and now it's mine too.
Mine.
This is great.
I wanna go higher.
Please,
you're doing it all wrong.
I wanna go higher.
Get up here
and double bounce me.
That's not how
we do things here.
Get up here
and double bounce me
or I'll tell everybody
about this place.
Come on.
God as my witness,
I will tweet it.
[WHIMPERING]
Unh! Double bounce me!
Why are you doing this?
Double bounce me.
Do it!
Pierce, that's enough.
I hate you. I hate you.
Double bounce me!
Father.
My legs. Ow!
Oh, my legs!
PIERCE:
Illegal trampoline!
They have an illegal
trampoline back there!
Black jeans?
Nice try, Michael Penn.
Bangs aren't covering anything.
Pegged jeans. Sweater balls.
Crow's feet.
Back hair into neck hair
into regular hair?
Look it up because you have it.
WOMAN: You are just mean.
Nice. Who taught you
how to be a juice box?
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
Don't worry,
I come in peace.
And whatever shampoo
you're using
seems to be doing the trick.
What do you want?
To restore the natural order.
What are these?
Destruct codes.
Get the blow torch over here.
Well, that seems
a little excessive.
Joshua.
We've been looking
for you all over.
Where are you going?
I got fired.
I'm leaving.
Joshua, we are so sorry.
Don't apologize.
It's my fault.
Guess that's what I get
for trusting some black guy.
[ALL LAUGH]
What?
When you found the trampoline,
I thought the only way
to protect it
was to let you use it.
Guess it goes to prove
what I already knew:
Non-whites ruin everything.
Oh, my God.
Joshua was racist?
That came out of nowhere.
Did it?
A place free from darkness.
And some are just
natural jumpers.
It's going to be a maze.
Maybe I just didn't
wanna believe it.
Maybe that's the lesson here.
Purity that demands exclusion
isn't real purity.
Maybe paradise is a lie.
PIERCE:
Not exactly.
Paradise exists.
Right here.
For once,
he's actually right.
Let me buy you
some ice cream.
My white guilt
is doing somersaults.
Worth it.
[♪♪♪]
Paradise.
Hey, horse-neck.
So, what's with the clothes?
I mean, you look like a toddler
who got dressed in the dark.
MAN: Ha, ha.
Snap, here it comes, y'all.
Look at your face.
It's like your mom
was a lizard
who got raped by a Muppet.
[CROWD LAUGHING]
That burn was brought to you
by the letter S, as in snap.
What?
Too hurt to respond?
That's right.
You don't have feelings.
The rest of us
feel ashamed of ourselves,
so we act like bitches
to make ourselves feel better.
But you did it to fit in.
And no matter how hard you try,
you never will.
[CROWD MURMURING]
Snap, snap, snap!
Give it up!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[MOUTHING]:
Thank you.
CHANG:
Snap! Snap! Snap!
Abed, are you okay?
That was so cruel.
I deserved it.
I should have never
been mean to anybody.
I tried to fit in,
I took it too far.
We took it too far. We became
the kind of women that we hate,
and we turned you
into a monster.
The kind of monster
that makes outlandish
statements about weight.
Those kind of things hurt,
even when they're not true.
And all because
we were insecure.
Everyone is. Even Tom Cruise
knows he's short and nuts.
We're at the mercy
of each other.
That's why there has to be
forgiveness on both sides.
SHIRLEY:
Oh, Abed.
Goodness.
What happened to Pierce?
Long story.
Men.
Yeah.
[WOMEN SCREAM]
Pierce, will you knock it off?
I told you,
I'm not controlling it,
there's a little man inside.
Hi.
PILOT: Pierce.
Listen, I wanted
to let you know, Pierce,
it's okay to exceed
the recommended daily dosage.
And don't let anybody
tell you different!
Who's going to be in charge
of making sure he doesn't OD?
What?
When did we start doing that?
Three, two, one.
BOTH:
♪ Troy and Abed
In the Morning ♪
And we're back with Greendale's
resident animal expert,
Star-Burns.
My name is Alex.
Star-Burns joins us
with his pet turtle, Shelly.
Now, I understand Shelly
can eat over five mice a day.
That's impressive.
Turtles don't eat mice.
What do they eat?
I don't know.
Pellets?
I have no idea.
That's disappointing.
That's not good.
What is going on? I was studying
for my econ midterm.
You guys walk in,
hand me this turtle
and tell me to smile
for the folks at home.
What folks at home?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
These things give you
salmonella, you know.
Let's go to Garrett
with a check on the weather.
It's still sunny.