[♪♪♪]
Anyone know how long
it takes papier-mâché to dry?
Longer than it took Duncan
to think up this assignment.
I think he's gonna
appreciate the work we did
expanding
our evolutionary chart.
Oh, Britta, can you hold up
the final stage of humanity?
I still think man
is gonna evolve into woman.
Not a dragon monster
with three legs.
Three legs?
JEFF:
Well, it's been real.
At least the paste smell has.
But I have a date to catch.
Or should I say
a catch to date.
Oof. I hope you just
came up with that.
Look out,
drive-by deaning.
I'm kidding.
Just a non-violent,
verbal reminder.
The local shelter is having
a Puppy Parade this afternoon.
ANNIE &amp; BRITTA: Aw.
Oh, I wanna lick it.
I expect all of you
to lend a paw.
Heh, heh.
Except you, Jeffrey.
I know you've got
a catch to date.
Oh, like you're famous
for your wit.
Puppy Parade?
I am in.
I wanna see if those
wiener dogs are born that way,
or if they start off normal
and then get wiener.
Abed, did you pick up my pen?
It's purple
with a gel grip.
Nope. I'm strictly
mechanical pencils.
More relatable?
It was just here.
You okay, Annie?
Chocolate?
Can I push you
to the parade, Pierce?
No, thanks. I don't want people
to see me as a handicap.
If anything, this chair
makes me more than a human.
You move it by blowing
into this tube.
It's the most expensive one.
I outbid three hospitals
for this baby,
and it was worth every penny.
[BLOWS]
Oh. Oh.
Wait.
Please, just wait.
I'm sorry, but I need to know
who took my pen.
Uh...
Sorry,
I don't see it.
Yeah,
sorry, Annie.
No. Not "Sorry, Annie."
We passed "Sorry, Annie"
eight pens ago.
I keep bringing pens
and you guys keep taking them,
and I'm afraid
I'm putting my foot down.
Okay.
Now Annie has made it clear
that this is an issue,
so from now on,
we need to be more
respectful
of her things, okay?
Okay.
Cool.
[SCREAMS]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
All right,
it's not on the floor,
so whoever accidentally took--
Not accidentally.
Accidents don't just happen
over and over
and over again, okay?
This isn't budget day-care.
Okay, whoever insidiously
and with great malice
aforethought
abducted Annie's pen,
confess, repent and relinquish
so we can leave.
TROY:
Maybe nobody took it.
Sometimes I think I lost
something important,
and it turns out,
I already ate it.
I didn't eat my pen, Troy.
I know I brought it,
and now it's gone.
Ah. I took a photo.
Aha.
Zoom in. See?
See? I took this
10 minutes ago.
My pen was on the table.
No one has come in
or out since.
One of you
has my pen right now.
Annie, it's a pen.
It's not a pen.
It's a principle.
[BOTH GASP]
Not a good time to get gum.
Okay.
Are we going
to the Puppy Parade?
Feels like a bottle episode.
PIERCE:
Again with the TV crap.
Hey, meatball,
did you take Annie's pen
to make life more like
Benny Hill or whatever you do?
Abed?
I wouldn't do that.
I hate bottle episodes.
They're emotional nuance.
I might as well sit with
a bucket on my head.
I have a photography project
to finish.
My grandmother's hands
aren't gonna take
close-ups of themselves.
Hasta la later.
Hmph.
Was that "hmph"
directed at me?
If the "hmph" fits.
I don't have your pen, Annie.
I'm always lending you supplies.
You never come prepared.
If it's so important,
have my pen.
That's my pen.
Whatever, people.
They're just things.
I don't suppose
you'd mind letting us
take a quick look-see
in your bag?
I'd very much mind, Annie.
There's no such thing as a quick
invasion of civil liberties.
[ALL GROAN]
Oh, man.
It starts with a quick look
into someone's bag.
Then it's a brisk peek
at our phone records.
And before you can say 1984,
the Thought Police
are forcy-worcing you
to bend and spread.
Are the Thought Police
gonna make love to us?
They find thoughts
in our butts?
I should've read that book.
Stop using the Constitution
as a baby blanket.
She invoked
the Freedom of Information Act
to request photocopies
of my notes.
Heh. That's pretty good.
Well, excuse me
for living free.
We all know
the pen's in your bag.
Yeah, come on.
Yeah, come on, just drop it.
Happy?
Not if that's a used Q-tip.
Ew!
Gross.
BRITTA: Yes, gross.
Welcome to the gross business
of martial law.
Welcome to what used
to be individuality
seized and disintegrated
by cowardly groupthink.
Welcome, my friends,
welcome to the machine.
It looks like you were wrong.
Britta does come prepared
for one thing.
[GASPS]
Or six. Big weekend?
Can't complain.
Razzle pzazzle.
PELTON [OVER PA]:
Attention, students.
The Puppy Parade
is starting on the quad.
Come quick. Every moment,
these puppies grow older
and less deserving
of our attention.
Whoa, whoa. Where do you think
you're going?
Have you ever gone to a Puppy
Parade halfway through, Britta?
It is pointless.
Then you clearly stole the pen.
The Patriot Act cuts
both ways.
Actually, it's one-sided.
That's the point.
Here's my point.
Whoever the thief is just
watched me get Guantanamoed.
I'd like to know who it is
so I can let them know
they have lost my trust.
It's a bottle episode.
We're sorry we looked
at your prophylactic equipment.
Your mistakes
are none of our business.
Oh, thanks, Shirley.
Let's rustle through
your tampons and wallet
so we can apologize to you.
I'm sure everybody here
knows I don't steal.
Have you checked? If you took it
by mistake, I forgive you.
If I took it, it's larceny.
If you find it under mother hen,
it's a mistake.
Mother hen?
We're the same age.
Sure, unless time is linear.
I'll make your ass linear.
That doesn't make sense.
I'll make your ass sense.
Don't get your panties
puckered.
We're all really thinking,
if the culprit
is among us,
statistically speaking,
it's Troy.
Yes, we were all
just thinking that, in 1856.
1856?
What if a ghost took the pen?
Please forgive him.
TROY: For what?
For stealing the pen, dummy.
Why would I take her pen?
I don't even like
having my own.
It's probably
under Pierce's cast.
He uses everything
to itch his legs.
We're on our third DVD remote.
If I took the pen,
I'd say so.
You probably forgot.
Been popping painkillers
like Tic Tacs.
Oh, yeah, right.
"Side effects, verbal dysphasia
and octopus loss."
I don't see anything
on this squirrel about memory.
Now I wanna know
who has it.
Nice try. That doesn't take you
off the list.
Jeff, you're in charge.
I demand you deal with this.
There's nothing to deal with.
I'll say.
Okay, all right, all right,
everyone breathe.
[INHALING]
You know what this is?
Yep.
Shut up.
This is a normal day
with friends
who are done studying
and a pen that rolled away.
Rolled away?
Or fell down someone's shoe.
Let's check shoes.
Annie.
Fine, fine.
Someone in this room
is hiding your pen.
Wanna know why?
They feel terrible.
They made a mistake.
They waited too long
to come forward
and now they feel bad.
They should.
Mm-hm.
Okay, okay. So, pen thief,
we understand what happened,
and we forgive you.
If you confess and apologize.
JEFF:
But here's the trick.
Because this person
now has no reason
not to come forward,
if by some chance,
I get to the count of three
and nobody comes forward, guess
what.
We have to accept that no one
has the pen, don't we?
[ALL GROAN]
Don't we?
Good. So here we go.
One.
Two.
[GASPS]
Pierce, you have something
to tell us?
Yes. Is it me,
or has it become really obvious
that Jeff took the pen?
BRITTA: Yes.
Definitely could be.
You wanna make a bet, you jerks?
Lockdown.
Abed, seal the doors.
Nobody leaves
until this pen shows up.
I don't like this.
Yeah, tell it to the pen
you might have.
Gwynnifer? Hi.
Yeah, it's me.
I can't make it.
Well, tell your disappointment
to suck it.
I'm doing a bottle episode.
[♪♪♪]
Okay.
You just became my hero.
Thank you.
No pen.
I can see that.
Why do you keep
taking that tone with me?
Oh, I'll field that.
If nobody else has this pen,
it means you realized
you had it
and were too embarrassed to say,
and we kill you.
I'm not hiding my own pen,
you paranoid weirdo.
Everybody stay within
each other's eyelines.
Me next, right?
Hold on.
Can we please consider
the threshold
that we are crossing?
We don't trust Abed?
He shredded my backpack.
He freed my pet monkey.
Because we corrupted him.
He's our innocent.
He put gum in your hair.
Empty the bag, Abed.
Pierce, you don't have a bag?
Giraffe.
Uh, Jeff, you don't have a bag?
I'd never deprive the world
of the part of my chest
the strap would cover.
Makes sense. What's left,
hugging and crying,
then we're done?
Wait, Abed,
why is my name in here?
That's mine.
And Shirley's and Annie's?
What is it?
BRITTA: Charts,
some kind of calendar?
That's my personal
private business.
"Annie, 4 on, 28 off,
next November 10th.
Britta, 5 on, 27 off--"
Oh, my God. Are you charting
our menstrual cycles?
What? Gross.
Abed, this is so personal.
And so accurate.
Creepy. I don't understand
why you would do this.
I can explain.
I thought you'd keep
yelling over me. I can explain.
I have trouble reading people,
I say the wrong things.
I noticed it was happening
more often with you three.
I noticed fluctuating patterns
and started graphing them.
By the time I realized
what I was measuring,
it had started to yield positive
results, so I kept doing it.
Were you ever
gonna tell us about this?
I feel so violated.
[ANNIE SOBBING]
Thanks.
More chocolate?
[WHIMPERS]
Aah! Get away from me.
Abed just became my hero.
Can I have a little--?
No!
Sheesh. Guess it's true what
they say about the sync-up.
If I could share
a few words of sarcasm
with whoever took this pen.
I wanna say thank you
for doing this to me.
Thought I'd have to suffer
through a Puppy Parade.
I prefer being entombed
in a mausoleum of feelings
I can neither understand
nor reciprocate.
Whoever you are,
can I get you anything?
Ice cream? Best friend medal?
Anything? Mm-mm?
Okay, sarcasm over.
You're last up, Shirley.
Dump your comedically huge bag
and end this.
Uh...
No, thank you.
Well, well, well,
Harvey Keitel.
Well, what do you know,
Henry David Thoreau.
My, oh, my, Mike Tyson.
Empty the bag.
No, I don't have Annie's pen.
I'm a Christian woman
that doesn't open her bag.
What did the Christian woman
think would happen?
You'd find it on the Muslim.
Real nice.
Nicer than you, condom carrier.
Dump the bag or you're guilty.
No.
Aah! Aah!
Oh, Lord, he's thrown a clot.
Pierce.
Call 911. Pierce-- Aah!
No. No.
Pierce, you didn't need
to do that.
Yes, I did.
All you guys do is talk,
leaving me to do the things
you won't do.
People like you are
the reason
we took so long
to get into Vietnam.
Is this what you were trying
to hide, Shirley?
A pregnancy test?
JEFF:
And more importantly,
are they seriously
marketing them to black women?
Guys, this is
a terribly childish way
to handle
this kind of situation.
Does this mean
you have a new boyfriend?
Who, who, who?
Not that it's anyone's business.
I recently reconnected
with my husband over Labor Day.
The Lord may have a plan
that doesn't include
that slut he ran away with.
You're not pregnant, Shirley.
Why does everybody think
I'm old? I'm around Jeff's age.
I have a uterus.
According to my charts,
you couldn't have conceived
Labor Day.
You would've been
ovulating on Halloween.
If you're gonna have
a pregnant woman,
I say go elevator labor
or go home.
Halloween?
Well, that's that, then.
Yeah, what a relief.
Looks like someone narrowly
avoided a mistake of their own.
Oh, or is it only bad
if you sleep with unmarried men?
The Bible
doesn't recognize divorce.
You marry a man,
he's your man.
After he marries
someone else,
if you jump into the sack
with him,
you're an angel, so long as
you don't use protection?
I'm so glad
you're enjoying this.
And I hope whoever stole
that pen enjoys it in hell.
Nice try, Stephen Fry.
Stephen Fry.
We all have an agreement.
Nobody leaves till we find it.
[GASPS]
SHIRLEY: Oh!
Yeah, here we go.
We are gonna find this pen.
We are gonna find that pen.
Oh...
And if we can't find it,
our children will find it.
Is it over here in these books,
the pen?
This incredible,
magical pen
that nobody knows
how it could disappear.
Oh, maybe it's right in here.
Guys, this is school property.
Can we just forget it?
It's a pen.
JEFF:
Oh.
It's a pen now?
Really?
It's not a principle anymore?
Now it's a pen?
Why the change of heart?
You're not seriously
accusing me. We searched my bag.
BRITTA:
Which is exactly the last place
you'd put it
if you found it
halfway through all this.
In fact, assuming that one of us
does have the pen,
who has the most incentive
to make sure it never sees
the light of day?
You wanna go there?
Yeah.
I'll go there,
Okay.
I was born there.
Really?
There's a placard there
commemorating me.
What's going on
and how can I help?
Annie, relax.
No, you relax, Jeff.
Or are you scared if you do,
my pen will fall out?
Oh, you precocious little bitch.
Okay, guys, guys,
hey, guys, stop.
You're being
completely illogical.
We need to flip the table,
divide by gender, then search
each other in our underwear.
What?
Now what?
Everybody shake.
Enough to dislodge.
Okay, anything hit the floor?
No.
What are those underwear
made out of?
Oh, they're an organic
soy-cotton blend.
This Gwynnifer
must be real special.
Don't you usually wear the
stripey Beetlejuice numbers?
What does she mean,
usually?
All right,
end of the road.
We've torn apart the room,
we've stripped.
There is absolutely
no place left...
[♪♪♪]
No.
[BLOWING]
ABED:
No.
No! No.
[TROY GRUNTING]
Damn it.
Broke my scissors.
Here. Be careful.
That's the last pair we have.
Also, don't cut his legs.
[GROWLS]
I'm worried
we've gone too far.
This is how super villains
are created.
Can't you just make
a speech about trust
throw in a few digs
at a celebrity
and put a ribbon
on this thing?
Abed, think about this
for one second.
If a single one of us
leaves this room
before we find that pen,
how can any of us trust anyone
in this group ever again?
What's your hurry?
I'm clothing myself.
I'm not comfortable
in my all-together
like you two anorexic jezeb--
Oh, I'm so sorry,
that was really mean.
I don't know
where that came from.
We've all been through
a lot today.
And I'm sure
this pregnancy scare's
been weighing on you
all week, right?
Mm-hm.
And maybe that's why
you took my pen?
What?
Where are you hiding it?
Oh, my goodne--
All right, here we go.
[JEFF &amp; TROY GRUNTING]
[ALL GROANING]
It smells like
a Waffle House sink.
Pierce, are you using Slim Jims
to scratch your legs?
Have we not gotten to a place
free of judgment yet?
This isn't it, this isn't it,
where is it?
Where's the pen,
where's the pen?
Where's the pen?
PELTON [OVER PA]:
It's getting a little chilly
outside,
so the animal wranglers asked
every student
to pick up a puppy
and hold it so they stay warm
while the volunteers
hand out puppy-sized hats.
Honestly, I don't know
why I'm even making
these announcements.
There can't be anyone
who isn't already on the quad.
Annie,
I'd just like to say,
on behalf of whoever
actually stole this pen,
I really am sorry
about all this.
I knew it was you.
It could be any of you.
For all we know, it's you.
I wish it were.
I really do.
I wish I could just find it
behind my ear.
I'd rather be that stupid
than have to think
any of us
might be inconsiderate.
After all we've been through,
it almost seems impossible.
It seems
less than impossible.
Something impossible
actually seems more likely.
Here we go.
A Winger speech to take us home.
What if a ghost took the pen?
Let him finish.
I am finished.
For real, honestly,
seriously, why not?
Why not just a ghost
took the pen?
Okay, I've been
saying that for hours.
And we should've listened
to Troy from the beginning.
Guys, look in your hearts
and answer this question
honestly.
What's more likely?
That someone in this group
doesn't belong
in this group or ghosts?
If we have to choose
between turning on each other
or pinning it
on some specter
with unfinished
pen-related business,
I'm sorry,
but my money's on ghost.
Well,
I'm not a religious person,
but I've seen specials
on the paranormal.
Anything's possible.
ANNIE:
Relative to the alternative?
It actually seems
more logical to me.
Why would a ghost want a pen?
Troy?
Okay, so I see it
as a lot like the movie
Paranormal Activity,
except for more boring
and fancy.
And I think in 1856,
it is possible
that a man was beheaded
while he was
writing in his diary
to his long-lost love.
And now he roams
the halls of Greendale
screaming for his pen
so he can write her
a love letter.
"I need her,
I need her,"
he screams
as he looks for a pen.
PELTON:
What the hell
did you people do in there?
Something
you could only dream of,
you non-miraculous
son of a bitch.
Non-miraculous?
Wait. Abed.
[♪♪♪]
[GIBBERS]
PELTON:
Now, who could resist falling
in love with our next float?
This Autumn Colors puppy
reminds us
that while the leaves
might be changing,
responsible pet ownership
is always in season.
Oh, here's a crowd favorite,
the Top and Tails float.
A champagne bath
and a red sports car?
Let's hope he's single.
Okay-- Oh, okay.
Well, this one feels
a little preachy. Oh.
Boo! Boo!