[BOTH BUZZING]
Hey, Buzby,
how are you today?
Not so great, Bumbleton.
I have a ton of pollen
to collect,
but I'm really tired.
Flying a little low?
Maybe you should get high.
Who's this?
This is Drugs.
Aren't Drugs bad?
No way.
Drugs are like special honey.
They give you a buzzzz.
Don't call me honey, honey.
Pierce,
Drugs doesn't say that.
You know, I don't say anything,
by the way.
I mean, I thought this show
was about drug awareness.
Who's gonna be aware of
a character that has no lines?
Also, I noticed on page 15
I get flushed down the toilet.
Consider yourself lucky.
Annie, question.
Is Pierce marijuana,
and does marijuana help
people work faster?
I thought it made them
custom-paint their vans
and solve mysteries.
Are you sure that my costume
is on backwards?
I felt more confident before.
I have a question.
I don't think my character
would say "tripping balls."
That's not a question.
I don't think my character
would say
"tripping balls," okay?
Let's remember
why we're doing this.
If our work helps one kid
make better choices,
then it will all be worth it.
I wish I had seen
a show like this.
Might have helped me
avoid mistakes.
BRITTA:
We're happy to do this for you.
But my school had
plenty of shows like this
and I think sitting through them
drove me to drugs.
You don't count.
You don't respond to anything.
Thank you.
Dean dong.
Heh, heh, heh.
I'm just checking in to see
how the Greendale
Anti-Drug Players are doing.
I talked to the counselor
at San Ramon Middle School.
There's gonna be at least
50 at-risk rugrats
coming here tomorrow for
your big world premiere.
JEFF: That's terrific.
SHIRLEY: That's nice.
With any luck, we'll get rid
of all those Charleston Chews
in the vending machines.
Dean Pelton, were you hoping
to participate in the show?
PELTON:
Oh, I would love to, Annie.
But as you can see from
my outfit, I have plans.
So, off to the airport Ramada.
How come he gets
a front stinger?
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Do you think bees
eat their own honey?
I'm sure they've
at least tasted it.
BRITTA:
This guy keeps texting me.
You don't like him?
I don't like flirting in text.
That's like saying you
don't work by electric light.
You want an active sex life,
part of it's texting.
I don't remember
asking your opinion.
CHANG:
Can't talk now.
Shirley, since I might be
the father of your unborn child
I made you a mix tape.
I hope you like Johnny Gill.
And since you probably
don't have a cassette player,
here's a list of used ones
on Craigslist.
Britta, are you
walking out of this room?
Uh, yeah.
You know you're gonna have
to acknowledge him eventually.
Don't know
who you're talking about.
Chang.
I know who you're talking about.
He doesn't exist.
Annie.
Ooh!
I'm sorry. A word?
Mm-hm.
I don't know if you know this,
but I did TV commercials
for Hawthorne Wipes,
family business, in the '50s.
Oh. Heh, heh.
I was kind of the Gerber baby
of moist towelettes.
Heh, heh.
That's great, Pierce.
Yeah. I've done a lot
of acting workshops.
Hm.
I do physical comedy,
funny dances,
foreign accents.
Accents?
Name any country.
Russia.
There are many tools
I can bring to the table
that I think the script
may be wasting.
Do you know what I think
is really great about this show?
The only real star of it
is the message.
Right, of course.
Is the message Jeff Winger?
He's on every page
of this thing, and--
I'll see you tomorrow.
You bet.
[PHONE BEEPING]
Britta left her phone.
She's getting a text message.
Let me see.
Oh. It's from Marcus.
"I'll be at the show
tomorrow night.
"Can't wait to see you.
Are you really wearing
a cat costume?"
Well, Marcus, you are in luck.
What are you doing?
Dragging Britta kicking
and screaming into 1997.
What'd you say?
"There's not much
to the cat costume.
But can't wait to show you
what's underneath."
How could you think
that's a good idea?
I got a better question.
How could it not be
a great idea?
[♪♪♪]
Thanks.
Here you go.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Wha--?
Pierce,
what are you doing here?
Never mind that.
There's a rapist in the hallway.
That's my landlord.
And If he wanted to rape you,
you'd be raped.
Did you follow me?
Let me answer your question
with two of my own.
What are you doing in
an apartment above Dildopolis?
And when did they open
a second location?
This is where I live.
It just happens to be
above a marital aid store.
I don't get it.
Aren't everyone's parents rich?
Well, I'm not speaking
to my parents.
After my breakdown,
my mom wanted to put
the problem behind us
and I wanted to deal with it,
so I went to rehab
and she cut me off.
What are you living on?
I saved.
Every penny from babysitting,
every birthday check.
Every dollar from the period
fairy when I was a kid.
I guess I thought
it would last longer.
Excuse me,
what's a period fairy?
The fairy
that gives you a dollar
every time
you get your period.
Does she still come?
Pierce.
You know, you and I
are very much alike, Annie.
We're both realists.
We're both cute.
And we'd both rather die than
let someone else control us.
I see the point
of this place now.
This crap hole is a monument
to self-reliance.
I found the drapes
in a dumpster.
Can you believe it?
Heh, heh. Yes.
You know, I wanna help, Annie.
Oh, no, no, no, Pierce.
Come on, now.
I'm not taking money from you.
It's not mine.
It's yours.
You've earned it
for being strong.
It's going to drop into your
hands from out of nowhere...
because I was never here.
I'm only taking this because
I'm worried about making rent
and the procedure
for selling eggs takes weeks.
You save your eggs
for a rainy day,
and I'll see you tomorrow.
Pierce?
Hey, why did you
follow me here today?
Oh, it was nothing.
It seems sort of pointless now.
I guess it was
to talk about the play.
And who cares
if I don't have any lines?
You know what, you should
do that line you improvised.
"Don't call me honey, honey"?
Yeah, that's it,
you should do that.
You were the Gerber baby
of moist towelettes, right?
Yes. Yes, I was.
MAN [ON FILM]:
And action.
Hello,
I'm Cornelius Hawthorne.
One rainy day, my son Pierce
and I were taking a stroll
when I discovered
the cleansing power
of moist cotton
fresh from the field.
Isn't that right, son?
It sure is.
It sure is, Dad.
Pierce, knock it off.
PIERCE:
I want to be
in the commercial too, father.
Well, then you should've done
better in your damn audition.
What's your name, son?
Nigel.
You're a good boy, Nigel.
Your father is a lucky man.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, guys, remember,
the most important thing
is to have fun.
The second is to know
all your lines
and not mess up a thing.
Actually, flip those.
Here we go, guys.
I took the liberty of
juicing up some of our bits.
Um, but--
You can't revise Annie's script.
And who uses Wite-Out anymore?
Why don't we look over
Pierce's changes
and see if
they improve things?
Hey, Crayon, do you know
where I can get some drugs?
I need them.
Unfortunately,
you can get them anywhere.
Anywhere?
PIERCE: I'm here.
Zabadazooey.
Good one.
ALL: Ha, ha, ha.
Doesn't seem to hurt
anything,
so let's get into costume
and break a stinger.
For the bees.
Annie, uh,
I don't feel comfortable
with the "zabadazooey" line.
The one you wrote?
I got it.
Let's give Jeff
the zabadazooey line,
and I'll come in
with "good one."
Yeah.
It's more in my voice.
I'm sure Jeff
is gonna reject that idea.
Yeah, you're probably right.
You're the producer.
By the way, is this your pen?
I think I put it
back in my pocket
after I wrote you
that check yesterday. Ahem.
I'll give it to you later.
I'll talk to Jeff.
Also, I think it'd be
better for my character
if I wear
his leather jacket.
Okay, welcome to Greendale's
Drug Awareness Show!
Okay, our volunteers
are handing out
drug-free baseballs!
Huh?
Next time
you think about drugs,
think about baseball instead.
You can't ignore me forever.
Okay, you probably can.
I don't know
why you want to.
My nephew Marcus actually goes
to San Ramon Middle School,
and he's coming
to see the show.
Marcus?
Your nephew?
He's 14. I actually thought
he didn't even like me.
But he texted me and he said,
"Can't wait to see you.
"I've been looking
forward to this.
You are the coolest aunt
in the world."
I hope that I don't
let him down.
You'll be great.
What does this mean?
It's eight, an equal sign
and a greater than symbol?
Let me see.
You better get changed.
I'll hang onto your stuff
for you.
Right.
Abed, we screwed up.
You know that text we sent?
It was to Britta's nephew.
He sent her an emotipenis.
What are we gonna do?
Fine. Screw you, Abed.
I can fix this.
"Marcus, I made a mistake.
I texted the wrong person
last night."
[PHONE BLEEPING]
"You called me by name.
It wasn't a mistake.
Don't be afraid."
Screw you, Abed.
"I was drunk.
We can't do this."
[PHONE BLEEPING]
"I'm drunk too.
On lust."
There's a picture.
Oh. That's disappointing.
Wow. Who does that?
That's--
Bees, you're up.
Cool cats, you're on deck.
TROY: Aren't drugs bad?
ABED: No way.
Drugs are like special honey.
They give you a buzzzz.
Don't call me honey, honey.
[KIDS LAUGHING]
Are you ignoring me
because I'm Korean?
You're Chinese.
Oh, there's a difference?
Shh!
It's because you're crazy.
There's something wrong
with you.
And the idea
that I was with you
means there's something
wrong with me.
And if this baby...
If you have
any humanity at all,
you will not make me
think about it.
Shirley, funeral.
[BOTH BUZZING "TAPS"]
Well, that answers my question.
Jeff Winger is sexy
even in a coffin. Hmm.
[BOTH CONTINUE BUZZING "TAPS"]
I'm here.
You're supposed to be on-stage.
I was looking
for a lighter.
What are you wearing?
This is a funeral.
I got this, Annie.
Uh--
I can't believe
Fluffy's dead.
I know I'm green,
but I feel blue.
[KIDS LAUGHING]
Look, it's Drugs with
a crazy wig and sparklers.
Pokémon!
[KIDS LAUGHING]
I don't think
that's right, Drugs.
Nobody asked you, Crayon.
[SHIRLEY SCREAMING]
I hope you're proud of yourself.
Look what you've done.
Oh, yeah?
Well, look what I'm doing now.
[IMITATES FARTING]
[KIDS LAUGHING]
It smells like
something died in here.
Should we get the dean,
call in a bomb threat?
Should we set off
the sprinklers?
It's not that big a deal.
The kids are into it.
I don't think they're
getting the message.
Do kids ever seem like
they're getting the message?
I think it's sinking in.
It's your call.
And he's about to get
flushed down a toilet
in the next scene.
And he'll be done.
[SIGHS]
I wish I had never even
met Drugs.
Who invited the nerd
from the beehive?
KIDS:
Ha, ha, ha.
PIERCE:
Drugs made you.
[ABED MAKES FLUSHING NOISE]
[PIERCE HUMMING]
How about you leave, Drugs?
[ABED MAKES FLUSHING NOISE]
Zip, zop, zoo.
[KIDS LAUGHING]
[KIDS CHEERING]
They want more.
I gotta go back out there.
But, Pierce, you were flushed.
That was the story.
That's what's
supposed to happen.
Being flushed doesn't mean
you're dead.
I could be a floater.
A floater is when
you have a number two--
I know what a floater is,
Pierce.
It just wouldn't make any sense
in the flow of the show.
And it sends
a mixed message.
Know what I think
is a mixed message?
Yesterday you couldn't pay
your rent, and today you can.
Come on, Annie.
You and I are alike.
We're independent,
we need each other.
[ALL FOUR CHEERING]
Bzzz. Getting rid of Drugs
was a great "i-bee-a."
I'm flying higher
than I ever have,
thanks to not Drugs.
Argh!
KID:
Chuck it at his nuts!
TROY: Hey!
BRITTA: Ow! Hey!
Hey!
I'm back.
[KIDS CHEERING]
Ain't no party without Drugs.
I love you, Drugs.
BOY:
Yo, pass it this way.
KIDS [CHANTING]:
We want Drugs!
Listen to that, Dad.
They're high on me.
I'm a god.
KIDS [CHANTING]:
We want Drugs!
PIERCE:
Where's that Nigel now?
And I haven't even used
my penis material yet.
Pierce, enough.
We're going back
to the original script
and doing some
damage control.
Damage?
The only damage
is me blowing the roof
off the universe.
I am not letting you
go back on that stage.
Well, maybe I won't be visiting
you late at night anymore
with a generous spirit.
You sick, sick,
sad old man.
This is why I didn't wanna
take money from my parents.
I don't want anybody
pulling my strings.
Wait, wait,
is he giving you money?
Not anymore.
Pierce bought his way in.
Annie sold out her message.
You've been
indulging this maniac?
Yes, I've been
indulging this maniac.
You're fired.
PIERCE: Fired?
Next time I'm at Dildopolis,
I will not be coming upstairs
to say hi.
The only reason we did this
was for you
and your stupid ideals.
It turns out
you don't even have any.
We supported you, Annie.
Yeah, Annie,
you're fired.
I'm sorry.
Here's the situation.
We've got 50 at-risk pre-teens
armed with baseballs,
chanting for drugs,
who just spent intermission
eating nothing but
Charleston Chews.
Thank God.
Hope you can top Act I,
is all I'm saying.
Oh. Hmm. Whoops.
Should we bail?
Works for me.
JEFF:
Wait.
Listen to those kids.
We just created
50 potential meth-heads.
The least we can do
is hit the reset button
and get that number
down to average.
That's a suicide mission.
Did someone say crazy person?
No.
Well, I heard it.
We want Drugs!
Greetings, you little snots.
[LAUGHING]
You're not Drugs.
Oh, but I am.
Disappointed?
Did you expect me
to stay the same forever?
Because that's not
what Drugs does, baby!
I'm gonna deep-fry your dog
and eat your mama's face.
And I'm gonna wear
your little brother's skin
like pajamas.
I control your lives
and there is nothing you can do.
Let's kill him.
Oh, bring it on, Bow Wow.
BOY: Get him.
CHANG: Ah!
[THUMPING AND POUNDING]
CHANG: Is that all you got?
I gotta tell you,
this is the greatest
chemical-dependency program
I have ever watched.
The way you got the kids
to think that they needed drugs.
And then having them realize
that dependence was the enemy.
That the price
was just too high.
Genius.
So now that the show is over,
what is the plan
for these bee costumes?
Hey, Marcus.
I'm Jeff.
I'm, like, uh,
Britta's boyfriend.
Look, dude, she started it.
She's just as into me.
No, listen,
I'm not mad.
I was just fooling around
and I sent those texts.
Gross.
Yeah.
It's disgusting, sending
those pictures to your aunt.
More disgusting than what
you texted to an underage boy?
I didn't know
you were you.
you weren't my aunt.
Okay. Let's just
call this a draw.
Britta doesn't need
to ever know about this.
Okay, I'd be happy to,
for a price.
That was brave of you.
I owe you an apology.
It was rude
to call you crazy.
Maybe I haven't been
giving you enough credit.
Oh, that's really sweet.
Tell you what,
why don't I go get Chang,
and you can tell him that
yourself.
Heh, heh.
Oh, no.
BRITTA:
My God, that was amazing.
Good job, you saved the day.
That's amazing.
Way to go, man.
Way to go.
BRITTA:
They beat the crap out of you.
TROY:
That's awesome.
It was okay.
I did lots of ad-libbing--
I'm so sorry.
Thank you so much.
That was amazing.
Even I learned something.
BRITTA: Oh, Annie.
CHANG: We did it.
Group hug, group hug.
CHANG: Oh, thanks.
BRITTA: Way to save the day.
ABED: Nice work.
CHANG:
Oh, love you.
BRITTA:
Did you get hit in the face?
Before you say anything,
I want you to know,
even though
I did nothing wrong,
I'm still gonna
give you money.
No, I can't take
your money, Pierce.
I can't go from depending on
my parents to depending on you,
which is why
I'm gonna get a job.
So you're cutting me off?
No.
Pierce, I know you don't
depend on anyone,
but you do depend on people
depending on you.
So I'm not gonna take
your money.
We're still friends?
Give me a day.
By the way, your mom
was the period fairy, right?
Hey, guys, I found my phone,
but has anyone seen my bra?
[♪♪♪]
[BEEPING ON PA]
MAN [ON PA]:
It's 2 a.m.,
time for Dildopolis'
Night Owl Deals.
Please be advised,
we will be closed
for Presidents' Day.
Just kidding.
Dildopolis never closes.
At Dildopolis, your privacy
is our top concern.
All store purchases will
show up on your credit card
as ABC Dildos, Incorporated.
Shopping till you drop?
Take a load off
at our in-store cafe
and enjoy an espresso or our
signature cinnamon biscotti.