So I go into the bathroom
with Tom,
and we both, you know,
take them out.
And I say,
"Size more? Try size less."
[GROUP CHUCKLING WEAKLY]
Oh. I wanna go to rehab
and compare penises with people.
All in good time, kiddo.
Well, uh, Pierce,
we're very glad
to have you back.
I'm assuming. Yeah?
Yeah.
ANNIE: Yeah.
So, what should we do now?
I don't wanna be that guy,
but I guess we should start
studying anthropology.
SHIRLEY: Yes.
Yeah.
Okay. Um...
Chapter four.
Hello.
Oh, thank God.
Oh. Yes.
Oh, my God.
Thank you.
What is it, dean?
Oh, ha-ha,
I have exciting news.
Vice president Joe Biden
has been visiting community
colleges across the country
as part of his Biden Time
Talking About Teaching tour.
Hmm. Folksy, yet progressive.
It does walk that line.
Anyway, his tour is taking him
in this neck of the woods,
and at 5:00 p.m. today,
he is stopping by Greendale.
Eat that, city college
and wash it down
with a nice tall glass
of suck it.
The vice president
is coming.
That explains the people
covertly surveilling
the campus.
Must be Secret Service.
Will your reality ever
come out
on Blu-ray so we can enjoy it?
We've been made.
Only problem,
Mr. Biden is supposed to be
meeting with the dean, hmm,
and the head
of our student government
which doesn't exist.
So we have seven hours
to elect a student president.
Ah. What am I gonna wear?
I mean, I could borrow
my sister's Uncle Sam outfit.
It's tailored for ladies,
but what else can I do
on such short notice?
Well, you cannot dress up
like Uncle Sam.
Or admit
you don't have a sister.
We're electing a student
president. I wanna run.
I have so many ideas
for improving the school.
Improving Greendale
takes more than ideas, Annie.
It takes time,
gasoline, matches.
Mm. Nice.
ANNIE:
Jeff, some of us care
about more than just fixing
our hair and sculpting our abs.
Wow, you got me pegged.
BRITTA:
Democracy. What a ruse.
There's no such thing
as a system
in which the masses--
Everyone wants you
to shut up.
And yet I won't. Case in point.
[CHUCKLES]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up, dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪
We tend to take democracy
for granted in America.
But the fact is,
men have fought and died
for the sacred right
we exercise today.
So anyone who wants
to be president,
line up
by the ice cream machine.
Your applause will determine
who gets into the primaries.
And yes, this is a ladies'
Uncle Sam outfit.
It's my sister's.
It was last minute.
I had no choice.
I wonder
if that's the same sister
that tweets to ask
if I think her brother's cute.
What happened to that pile
of campaign fliers?
I hung them all up.
Real nice.
Is it too much to ask you
to pitch in?
I'm sorry, Annie.
I'm not the worker bee type.
I'm more
of a silverback gorilla
with the claws of a lion,
the teeth of a shark,
and quiet dignity
of a tortoise.
All right, first up is this
fella. Let's go, come on.
All right,
tell everybody your name.
Garrett.
Okay, Garrett.
And why
do you wanna be president?
I wanted ice cream,
so I got in line--
Okay, okay.
He wanted ice cream.
So, what do we say, gang? Does
he make it to the next round?
By applause.
Oh, we've got
our first nominee.
The bar has been set.
All right, stand to the side.
Stand to the side.
At least worker bees
can set aside their egos
and join together
to support a larger cause.
Oh, right, because politics
are all about larger causes.
Face it, Annie.
Politics are all about ego,
popularity
and parlor tricks.
Don't kid a lawyer.
Well, if I see one, I won't.
Oh, it's a girl.
Look at this.
She's got a yellow shirt
and a hat.
Who are you, sweetie?
Uh-- Vicki.
Who's up for some Vicki?
Abed Nadir, I'm Special Agent
Robin Vohlers.
This is Special Agent Keenlan
of the Secret Service.
Will you submit to a search
of your belongings?
Sure.
How did you notice
the campus was being observed?
I guess I noticed
because I'm used to being
the only observer.
Well,
we're not used
to being noticed.
That sounds a little sad.
He's clean.
Although
I could issue a warning
for this bootleg
of The Last Airbender.
Where were you a week ago?
You can keep it.
Well,
another one makes the cut.
Congratulations, Leonard.
Pbbt!
PELTON: Oh, yes, wonderful.
Next up, Annie Edison.
[SCATTERED APPLAUSE]
My name is Annie Edison.
And if elected,
I promise to make Greendale
the signature
community college
of the entire western
three quarters
of the Greendale area.
Annie!
Oh!
Looks like
you're in the running, Annie.
it is hard not to be. Next up.
I'm sorry, I got the heat,
I gotta go.
I believe that humankind
need not be governed.
I don't care.
Well, it's good to know
there's a floor
on this thing. So...
Thank you, Ms. Perry. Okay.
Oh, Annie,
I'm so proud of you.
Thanks.
People love you.
I believe
this campus is a good place,
filled with good people
who just need someone
to protect their interests.
PELTON:
Jeff Winger.
CROWD:
Oh.
My name is Jeff.
I'm no politician.
I'm just a fella.
I think
that beer should be cold
and boots should be dusty.
I think 9/11 was bad.
And freedom,
well, I think that's just
a little bit better.
STUDENTS:
Yeah.
Whoo!
[♪♪♪]
Yeah.
[CROWD CHEERING LOUDLY]
ABED:
Countdown has begun.
Tonight, one student
will be president,
while the rest
will simply be.
For Greendale Campus TV,
I'm Abed Nadir.
I'm Troy "Butt Soup" Barnes.
That's my name.
As we head
into the first round,
there are eight candidates.
TROY: Annie Edison.
ABED: Smart, attractive.
Leonard Rodriguez.
TROY: Did he change his name?
ABED:
He's trying to court
the Hispanics. Alex Osbourne.
TROY:
Creepy, seems Greek,
possible drug dealer.
Jeff Winger.
ABED:
They call him Hot Wings.
TROY: Magnitude.
ABED: He's a one-man party.
Pierce Hawthorne.
The wizard of wet wipes.
TROY: He's got night terrors.
ABED: Garrett.
TROY:
That guy's just a mess.
It's like God spilled a person.
ABED:
And Vicki.
Yellow shirt, hat, girl.
You know, you gotta ask
yourself right now, Abed,
what's up with politics?
You're right, Troy.
I hear they're getting
ready to start.
We'll turn it over
to coverage of the debates.
Who's that?
Special Agent Vohlers.
U.S. Secret Service.
Do you just constantly have
your own side adventures?
Yep.
Me too.
Knock it off.
You're not running sincerely.
You're not even interested
in student government.
I know, and yet,
the people love me.
It's almost as if politics
were a huge joke.
Okay, look.
I'm sorry I asked you
to hang my fliers,
but I suggest
you drop out right now
because not only
will I beat you,
I will make you cry.
Oh, I feel a slight ego
blowing in from the east.
Gonna feel my foot
blowing in from the south.
Bring it on, Ponce de Leon.
I'm gonna, Greg Muldunna.
It's a real guy. He owns
a mattress store downtown.
You can look it up.
Hey, Vicki. Psst.
Vicki, look at me. Psst.
I'm going to crush you.
Pierce.
ANNIE:
Stop that.
I'm gonna eat your brains,
Vicki.
Gonna slurp them out of
that melon you call a head.
PELTON:
A reminder to all candidates,
your microphones
are currently on.
Well, they better be
because I'm on fire up here.
You freak people out,
you know that?
You look weird.
Because of your overbite.
Okay,
let's just get started.
Welcome to the Greendale
Community College
presidential debate.
Candidates, if elected,
what will you do?
Oh, Annie.
I'm running on a platform
of school improvement.
If I'm elected,
the black mold will be removed
from the east stairwell.
The assailant known only
as The Ass Crack Bandit
will be brought to justice.
And I will balance
the school's budget
by eliminating
administrative redundancies.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
Okay. I'm in the room.
Thank you, Ms. Edison.
Mr. Winger?
Well, that's
an important question.
And it's important
to students like Jeremy,
who told me that he is majoring
in astronomy
and is supporting
two children.
It's an important question
to Maria,
who's a beautiful Latina
born in Nicaragua
working in the cafeteria.
MAN: Yeah.
JEFF: What will I do, dean?
Well, these people
don't want me
to say what I'll do.
They want me
to do what I'll say.
Aw.
[CROWD CHEERING]
They love it when you shuffle
the words around.
MAN: Go, Jeff.
Magnitude?
Pop, pop.
Oh, no.
[CROWD LAUGHING
&amp; APPLAUDING]
Same question.
Same answer.
Pop. Pop.
[CROWD LAUGHING
&amp; APPLAUDING]
A few questions?
Okay.
Was there a specific reason
you had to repeat first grade?
I didn't know
how to use scissors.
I sat in the middle
of the seesaw.
I found the distinction between
duck and goose arbitrary.
Couldn't you just pick
the sixth kid?
That's what I...
Would have done.
I went with four.
Jeez, get a room, you two.
Pierce Hawthorne,
your platform?
My platform will be one
high enough
to push Vicki
off to her death.
Ugh!
PELTON: Vicki?
Looks like Vicki
is out of the race.
Well, then I am too. I was only
here to get back at her
for not lending me a pencil.
Oh. Wow. Well...
ANNIE:
Can we get back on track here?
I just wanna get the black mold
out of the east stairwell.
I just want
to clean up Greendale.
Are you saying
Greendale is dirty?
Oh, boo.
CROWD: Boo.
Well,
of course it's dirty.
Everyone knows that.
I don't, Annie.
I think it's clean.
I think
it's the cleanest school
in the entire country.
You know it is.
TROY:
Jeff Winger's got this thing
in the bag.
ABED:
Sure does. Say what you will,
but people just like the guy.
Read my lips.
No matter what you're told,
we have to clean the mold.
That's right, people.
ALL [CHANTING]:
No matter what you're told,
we have to clean the mold.
No matter what you're...
ABED: This is interesting,
Annie Edison has reduced
her platform to one issue
and turned that issue
into a sound bite.
TROY:
And it rhymes. People love it.
This election's become
a race.
According to our polls,
the campus is almost
evenly divided.
Keep in mind
the margin of error
is about 98 percent.
Could be higher.
We don't even know
how to do margins of error.
We're taking a break.
Stay tuned.
They have to. It's
closed-circuit television.
Don't know what that means.
MAN: And we're out.
Apple juice, please? Freshly
squeezed, or so help me God.
Abed,
those guys in the suits
are trashing your dorm room
real bad, bro.
[♪♪♪]
What are you doing?
Random spot check.
Stay out of our way.
Nothing suspicious.
Glenn, bring the car around.
What are you looking for?
Fertilizer, car battery,
PVC piping.
Anything suspicious.
Because you think
I'm suspicious?
Or you wish I was suspicious
so that you would have
an excuse to see me.
This was a spot check.
Do you like me?
That's not really relevant.
That's close enough.
Are you sure?
You smell like nice soap.
I have to go.
I'm sorry you weren't
a more obvious
potential threat
to the country.
People are pretty excited
about this black mold issue.
For my closing statement,
I'm thinking about smashing
a watermelon.
If I admit
politics are stupid,
will you stop
making them stupid?
You're gonna split the vote,
Star-Burns is gonna end up
president.
I'm trying
to get something done.
And you deserve
to be allowed to do it?
You're entitled
to be president?
The gloves are coming off.
You understand me?
I have an audio-visual
presentation.
Wow, I'm shaking.
You should be.
PELTON:
All right, let us resume.
Star-Burns,
we haven't heard from you
on this black mold issue.
Yeah, I actually withdraw
my candidacy.
I fear a political career
will shine a negative light
on my drug dealing.
Thank you.
CROWD:
Boo.
Dean, before this election
stops being about the issues,
I have a question
for my opponents.
What's your favorite color?
Mine's a three-way tie.
Red, white and blue.
[CROWD CHEERING &amp; APPLAUDING]
Magnitude, a response?
I think you know, dean.
ALL:
Pop, pop.
[CROWD LAUGHING &amp; APPLAUDING]
I set him up.
I have an audio-visual
presentation, dean.
Oh, that sounds interesting.
What's your presentation?
My presentation
is a copy of Jeff Winger's
1997 audition tape
for MTV's The Real World.
What? What?
Let's just roll it. Thanks.
I'm Jeff Winger
and I'd love to be
on MTV's Real World: Seattle.
So check this out.
[PLAYING GEORGE MICHAEL'S
"FAITH" ON GUITAR]
♪ Well, I guess
It would be nice ♪
♪ If I could be on MTV ♪
♪ So please, please
Take a look at me ♪
♪ For the Real World ♪
♪ Oh, I'm gonna apply twice ♪
[WHISPERING]
Where did you get that?
Folks, who do you want
shaking Joe Biden's hand
at 5 p.m.?
Me or--?
[CROWD LAUGHING]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Shut up. I was like 19.
We've all been 19, Jeff,
and none of us did this.
None of us.
Pop, pop.
I hate you.
I hate this school.
And I hope you all get
black mold poisoning.
PELTON:
Oh, Jeffrey, no.
JEFF:
I hate you! I hate you!
No, Jeffrey, no.
♪ You gotta have Jeff
Jeff, Jeff ♪
[♪♪♪]
Are you in here?
JEFF:
Yeah, to be alone.
I've already established
the men's room doesn't work.
You have an apartment.
JEFF:
There are people
in the parking lot
singing that song.
I went too far. I'm sorry.
I didn't know
it would be that bad.
You knew. You didn't care.
But don't apologize.
I got what I deserved.
I am a gross, jaded adult
with control issues
that couldn't let a young,
bright, idealistic kid
run for president.
Wait, isn't there
a final round of debates?
Yeah. I--
You guys. You're missing it.
Troy, I'm out.
Me too.
I withdrew my candidacy.
Nobody that treats a friend
the way I did
is fit to represent
the student body.
Yeah, I know you're both out.
I'm saying you're missing it.
It's the political showdown
of the century. Come on.
Pop. Pop.
Pbbt!
MAGNITUDE:
Pop. Pop.
Pbbt!
You should've stayed.
You're the only real candidate.
I was just another jerk
trying to win a contest.
You were right
the whole time.
I just couldn't admit it
until I saw you
running away crying.
Yay.
I care what you think
about me, you know?
Yeah, well,
I care what you think
about me.
That's why this happened.
Okay, well...
Resolved, then.
Resolved.
[♪♪♪]
When we seek to destroy others,
we often hurt ourself
because it is the self
that wants to be destroyed.
Pierce, you're not usually
so poignant.
Well, Vicki finally lent me
her pencil.
Oh, my God, Pierce.
Go to the health center.
Yeah.
TROY:
We've reached
the end of election road.
Arguments made,
pops popped.
Hearts have been stirred,
perhaps broken.
The only thing that remains
is to tally the vote
in this matchup
between the youthful,
charismatic Magnitude
and Leonard Rodriguez.
Two men fighting
for the same piece of earth.
One recently born,
one soon to die.
A competition reflecting
the pointlessness of life.
Pull up, Abed.
You're in a nose dive.
I'm told that Dean Pelton is
prepared to announce a winner.
We take you live
to across the room.
Okay. Here we go.
Thank you, Sergio.
With 11 votes cast--
Eleven, come on, people.
The landslide winner
of the student election
with seven votes is
South Park.
Okay. You know what?
I recall this is why
we abolished student government
in the first place.
This is exactly
what happened 10 years ago.
Hey, how hard is it
to get rid of black mold?
What do we need,
buckets and sponges?
I don't actually know.
I'll look it up.
Milady.
TROY:
Well, there you have it.
In a shocking upset, Comedy
Central series South Park
has been elected president
of the Greendale student body.
Not that shocking to me,
I voted for it.
For real? Me too.
We can never stop
being friends.
As we begin gearing up
for next year's election,
for GCTV,
I'm Abed Nadir saying:
Did you know
you could make napalm
out of dish soap
and cat food?
What?
Why would you say that?
Hmm?
[♪♪♪]
[SIREN WAILS]
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
Vohlers. Yeah.
Sir, we're gonna have
to move on to city college.
There's an elevated
threat level at Greendale.
But don't worry.
I'll check it out. Personally.
BIDEN:
Whatever.
I just had a dream
that I was a regular president.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
WOMAN [ON TV]:
You've done so much
for our city.
Kickpuncher, is there anything
that we can give you?
Don't call me Kickpuncher.
Call me David.
[MUSIC ENDS]
This was fun.
Maybe you can observe me
having dinner next time.
Honk twice for yes,
once for no.
[VAN HORN HONKS TWICE]
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.