[♪♪♪]
[ALL CHATTERING]
Annie, two gifts? Thank you.
I wanted to get a doll,
and since the father
might be Andre or Chang,
I wanted all ethnic
bases covered.
So there's a little
African-American girl...
and a letter
from the manufacturer
promising to expand
their selection.
Oh, is everyone enjoying their
egg rolls and/or mieliepap,
a traditional maize porridge
popular in Ghana?
Annie, baby showers
can be race neutral.
Yes, thank you
for trying to be inclusive,
but regardless
of any biological happenstance,
this baby'll be raised
by Andre and I.
That's right.
I seem to recall a story
about a man named Joseph
who raised a baby
that wasn't his.
History's greatest chump.
We're talking
about Joe Kennedy, right?
It's cool. If it's mine,
I'll be a lovable uncle.
Okay, a creepy uncle,
final offer.
From me and Troy.
When your child's a scavenger
of the nuclear wasteland,
water will be worth gold.
We wanted to get
a sawed-off shotgun,
but those were pretty
expensive already.
You people eat this?
I've never seen that
in my life.
You really shouldn't say
"you people."
Pierce was having trouble
quitting offensive phrases.
We've created
a bargaining system.
We traded "you people"
for his other favorite phrases.
Yeah, I really got
Jewish-personed out of that one.
CHANG:
Here, open mine.
Thank you.
[CHUCKLES]
A cigar cutter,
Maxim and hot sauce.
It's a theme gift.
Yeah, the theme is
"stuff lying around
my apartment."
Sorry I'm late. Can I get
a ni hao up in this hizzy?
Why is everyone in this school
obsessed with race?
White people problems.
Ooh. That looks fun.
Oh, Troy, Abed.
Who's that cute guy
that I saw you outside
with earlier?
Lukka, our friend.
He's in Troy's class.
He's awesome. He has an accent,
rolls his cigarettes
and plays
the same video games as us.
We like him a lot.
So you're not allowed
to bone him.
You just guaranteed
she'll bone him.
[MOANING]
Who am I kidding?
I should be putting this right
on my thighs.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up, dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪
Abed,
there's a guy on your 6.
I'm taking out my 9 mm.
Please. In my country,
we give 9 mm
to little girl for sweet 16.
Try grenade launcher.
Cool.
[EXPLOSION AND SCREAMING
ON VIDEO GAME]
Easy peasy, lemon squeezy.
Knock, knock.
Hey, I was just stopping by.
Oh, is this a bad time?
TROY &amp; ABED: Yeah.
Gentlemen,
that's no way to treat a girl
that looks this way. Come in.
I'm Lukka.
Britta.
Like Britney Spears?
Exactly like Britney Spears.
♪ Hit me
With your genie's bottle ♪
♪ Rub it all over me ♪
Britta was just leaving.
No. Stay.
Visit with your friends.
I must go anyway.
Ohh.
I'm cooking podvarak.
I never had that.
I could make for you.
TROY &amp; ABED: Ohh.
I'll give you my number.
BOTH: Oh!
LUKKA: You are her boyfriends?
BOTH: No!
Ha, ha. I love these guys.
They make funny
with their mouths.
Here you go.
I leave.
BRITTA:
Okay.
What? He asked me out.
Not allowed.
Not allowed?
You'll ruin him.
Ruin him?
Stop repeating.
Stop re-- Remanding me.
Explain why I'll ruin him.
You date guys
that we think are cool,
and when you don't
like them,
you tell us horrible things
about them.
Name one guy.
Carl, Todd, Kyle, Richard.
Fred. Tall Kyle.
Jeff.
Jeff. Jeff? I ruined Jeff?
Jeff "Nipple Play" Winger?
No, we're still hanging out
with him.
How's it going, Jeff?
Promise
you won't date Lukka,
I'll give you a sweatshirt
I made for paintball.
Pssh! You should've
given me one a long time ago.
I kicked your asses.
[IMITATES LASER GUN]
Don't date Lukka.
Hit my genie bottle?
What the--? What was that?
[♪♪♪]
Oh, oh. Jeff?
I'm hoping you can
help me with something.
Sure,
let's have a look here.
Pieces of paper
stapled together,
a lot of writing.
This is as far as I can go.
I don't want you to read it.
Help me get Chang to sign it.
It's a little something
I had an attorney draw up.
This is a forfeiture
of parental rights.
Mm-hm.
Better safe than sorry.
Why do you need me to make
Chang sign away his baby?
Isn't he living with you?
Not cool.
You have a rapport with him.
Besides, as your friend,
can I tell you?
Don't poke that bear.
I think, right now,
you're as protected
as you can get.
I don't see Chang as being
a real hands-on baby-daddy.
Now we're in the business
of knowing what's going on
in Chang's head, huh?
[FOOT TAPPING]
Fine, for the child.
God bless you.
Not lately.
[♪♪♪]
I'm, um-- I'm so sorry,
but could you just
not tell Troy and Abed
that we went out tonight?
No problem.
It's just--
Um, they're just really
worried
if you and I,
you know, see each other,
it's gonna affect
your friendship with them.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
I can keep a secret.
Oh, good.
I'm from the Balkans.
There are many things
I try not to talk about.
Oh.
Lukka, I knew it.
I knew there was pain
in there.
Just so you know,
you can talk to me
about anything.
[SIGHS]
So much killing.
The corpses
stacked like firewood.
The rivers red
with their blood.
I miss it so much.
Lukka.
Mm. Wait, just, um--
Just to clarify.
When you say you miss it,
it's like
you have survivor's guilt.
You wish you were back
over there,
defending the motherland?
Yes, I miss cleansing
our fields and forests
of the unclean people
who stole my country.
I miss the smell
of the villages burning. Heh.
I miss the way they used to run
from our tanks in fear.
[TROMBONE PLAYING]
Damn it. My neighbor
is jazz musician.
Hey, Spencer. Come on, man.
I have woman in here.
Great. He really knows
how to kill the mood.
[DOOR OPENS]
What are you doing?
Did you look for a job?
I was going to, but I noticed
your coffee table was wobbly,
so I decided to fix it.
Agh!
Agh! Must be the floor.
Don't saw the floor.
Don't saw anything.
I'm tired of confiscating saws.
Give me that.
Take this.
Parental rights?
You're adopting me?
It's from Shirley. It gives her
and Andre the baby.
Sign it.
Oh, and if anyone asks,
this was my most convincing
speech ever.
[♪♪♪]
Why are you crying?
Ugh. Don't tell me
you wanted to be a father.
I don't know.
Maybe.
I mean, what if this is
my last chance?
Between you and me,
I don't Chang a lot of chicks.
But fathers are responsible.
They have jobs.
You crash
on people's couches
and twitch in your sleep like
a dog dreaming of a rabbit.
It's real. You don't-- Wait.
[♪♪♪]
So you're saying
if I get a job
and my own apartment,
Shirley might let me be part
of my baby's life?
Yes.
That's exactly
what I'm saying.
So does that mean I can...?
Go for it.
[CHUCKLING]
Where do you keep getting
these?
[♪♪♪]
Hey, guys.
Where are you going?
Grabbing lunch for a video-game
session with Lukka.
Fork foods. Don't wanna grease
up the troops.
Speaking of Lukka,
how much do you know
about him?
Why?
You start dating him?
You wanna tell us
horrible things?
What? No.
Good. Lukka's gonna teach us
how to break the will
of an entire village.
That sounds horrific.
Ugh. Girls are so
undesensitized.
[♪♪♪]
Jeffrey.
JEFF: Hey, guys.
Hi.
So how'd the talk go
with Chang?
About that. I gave
my most convincing speech ever
and it didn't take.
Didn't take?
We're not giving him a perm,
we just need him to sign.
"Need" is a strong word.
I think Shirley would feel
comfortable
if we had something
in writing.
However, I believe
that we can handle
whatever obstacle
comes our way.
Aww. Baby.
Well, good morning,
everybody.
Did you see
the stock market today?
Up, down, pick a direction.
Huh?
I don't know about you,
but I've been circling
these want ads all morning.
Now, who wants to take a break
and build a birdhouse?
Chang, what's going on?
Just getting my act together.
I got a baby coming.
I can almost hear
the pitter-patter
of Chinese feet
across the treetops.
And when that happens,
I gotta be the best dad
I can be.
Right, Jeff? Huh?
Come on,
don't leave me hanging,
my main mentor.
Hey,
is that a reason to leave?
Hm?
Jeffrey. Excuse me. Jeffrey.
SHIRLEY: Excuse me.
Let me ask you a question.
Why do I have to put the VCR
on three if Bones is on five?
Jeff. Jeffrey.
I know you're not gonna make
a pregnant woman run.
[♪♪♪]
I know you're not gonna make
a pregnant woman walk
this distance between us.
So I ask you to help me,
and you take that as an
opportunity to get Chang out?
Hey, who am I to stand
in the way of someone?
Am I daytime television?
Very cute.
How cute's it gonna be
when that lunatic
is dangling my baby
over a lion cage
on alternate weekends?
Pretty cute.
Are they baby lions?
New low, Jeff. Even for you.
Shirley--
Mm!
Right. I'm not gonna make
a pregnant woman storm off.
Mm-mm.
Look at them run.
They must die
like the maggots that they are.
Points for killing villagers.
He's amazing. I thought I knew
everything about this game.
[KNOCKING]
Britta.
Hi, Lukka.
No!
Unbelievable.
Guys, calm down.
I'm just here for my
"Trekkies do it in
the final frontier" hat.
That's my hat.
Really?
Are you sure?
Yep.
[GUNFIRE AND SCREAMING
ON VIDEO GAME]
Hey, Lukka, you are really good
at this game,
and there must be a reason
that you are so good
at this game.
Though your flirtation
technique is hilarious,
it's distracting. Lukka is
kicking serious ass right now.
He just set fire
to a farmers' market.
Bang, bang, you're dead!
Ha-ha-ha.
Save your tears
for your dog mother in hell.
[TROY &amp; LUKKA LAUGHING]
[ABED BARKING]
Okay, fine.
Wait a minute.
You have DVD Blu-ray disc,
Kickpuncher 3:
The Final Kickening?
You let me borrow, no?
Sorry. Thanks to Pierce,
who kept writing
"this side up" on my discs,
I have a strict no-lending
policy on my DVDs.
What would happen
if somebody broke that rule?
They'd be dead
to me forever.
Maybe we watch Kickpuncher 3:
The Final Kickening together.
BRITTA:
Yes, Lukka, maybe we do.
Maybe we do.
Would you please leave?
I don't wanna
play anymore.
I feel sick.
She's strange.
[♪♪♪]
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Can't talk
till I see my face in this.
Well, can I give you
some advice, dad-to-dad?
Hold on, hold on.
Where's my pipe? Okay.
What's on your mind,
neighbor?
Look, it's great you're trying
to get your life together,
but for your sake
and for Shirley's,
you need to relax a little.
Oh, I see what's going on.
Yeah?
You're scared.
No.
Feel me coming up
on your tail, huh?
No, no. Man, listen.
I've been a father
for 11 years
and a good one
for nine of those.
I'm there when they're sick,
pick them up from school.
Help them
with their homework.
It's not how you act,
it's what you do.
Well, I do.
You think that pool table
put aluminum siding on itself?
[FABRIC TEARS]
Yeah, see,
that's not what
I'm talking about.
That's too bad.
What did that?
I'll go ahead and consider
that point missed.
[♪♪♪]
I got your text.
Something happened.
My Kickpuncher 3: The Final
Kickening DVD is missing.
That's awful.
Somebody took it?
Who would--?
Wait, Kickmuncher 3?
Wasn't that the movie
that Lukka was--?
You don't think--?
Unless...
You don't suppose--
However-- No.
That would mean
that you guys
would have to stop
hanging out-- No!
We have video of you
taking the DVD.
What?
LUKKA [ ON COMPUTER]: Watch,
I got this guy--
Lookit. Lookit.
TROY:
Oh. One more, brother,
you get-- Yeah.
You have a security camera?
It's for a documentary
I'm making.
It's footage of me watching
dailies, but it comes in handy.
I don't understand
why you would pin it on Lukka.
Now you're just ruining
cool guys for fun.
It's just cruelty, Britta,
you're inhuman.
You're an inhuman person.
A monster.
Lukka's a monster
for realsies.
I did this so you'd stop hanging
out. He's a war criminal.
You're embarrassing yourself.
In what war is he a criminal?
The battle
for our affections?
Uh, how about the genocide
in the Balkans?
Mm, yeah. You would say that.
You just got caught red-handed
borrowing a DVD
without permission.
[♪♪♪]
You guys
have to believe me.
He's so much worse
than Tall Kyle.
[CHANG &amp; KIDS
SINGING IN SPANISH]
Hey, jefe.
[KIDS SPEAK IN SPANISH]
What are you doing?
Who are these tiny people?
I picked up Shirley's kids,
and I'm helping out
with their homework.
Hey, kids.
Hey.
Hey, watch the cardigan.
What? Why?
To prove
I'm a responsible dad.
This proves
you're a kidnapper.
I am nuts!
Get with the program!
What have I done?
I can't believe
I said
you could be a father.
I can be.
You can't be anything,
you never will.
I pretended
to have faith in you
to get you
out of my apartment.
Now, call Shirley
and beg forgiveness.
Kids, why don't you get
your stuff together?
I'll take you home.
Who's Shirley?
Shirley's your mom,
dumb-ass.
Our mom's name is Loquanda.
Hey, hey. That's racist.
Wait, is your mom's name
really Loquanda?
Yeah. You said
you're a friend of hers.
Why didn't you know that,
dumb-ass?
I do. I was just playing
an educational game with you.
Right.
Don't give me that lip.
Kids, you mind waiting
in the hallway?
Yeah, no problem.
Go ahead.
I want you
to understand something.
Yes.
You are a horrible human being.
I will never feel sorry
for you again.
I don't care
what happens to you,
and when I get back,
I want you gone.
Believe me. I will definitely be
far, far away from here.
[♪♪♪]
Hi, policemen. How much do you
pay for anonymous tips
about kidnappings?
Okay, fine.
This one's on me.
[♪♪♪]
You're free to go.
Here's your wallet,
keys and pasties.
They're nipple guards
for running.
Olympic athletes use them.
I worked
at a maximum-security prison,
those are the gayest things
I've seen.
Well, I find that
hard to believe.
Jeffrey,
I spoke to the boys' mother,
she's not gonna press
charges. Are you okay?
Oh, I'm fine. I spent the night
learning arts and crafts
from my cellmate, Chabo.
Did you know
you can make an ashtray
using a snitch's forehead?
Yeah.
Look, Shirley,
I'm sorry I tried to capitalize
on your situation with Chang.
Apology accepted.
Punishment is time served.
There's no cell
that can hold Chang.
OFFICER:
Cut it out, get down
the hallway. Come on.
CHANG:
Winger.
Thank God you're all right.
I've been looking all--
Hey, Tracy, what's up, baby?
Why are they arresting
Chang?
Loquanda wasn't pressing
charges.
I talked her
into going after Chang
for child endangerment.
He could get
three to five years.
You sure
that's what you want?
Because if we put
our heads together,
we could be rid of him
for 20 to life.
Really?
Oh, absolutely.
I'd testify that he tried
to sell those kids to me.
Throw in that he was
teaching them Spanish,
any DA worth his salt
could make a case
for trafficking.
I like how you're thinking.
What is wrong with you two?
Why are you doing this?
I'm doing this for us.
We have a second chance.
I want everything
to be perfect.
That's what you wanted
the first time around.
You did everything
to make everything perfect,
and look what happened.
You cheated because I wanted
what was best for our family?
No. I cheated
because I was a coward.
You took me back
because while I was gone
you learned to accept
the bad with the good.
Oh,
that's the Greendale effect.
Our school motto
is "lower your standards."
Look, I know you are ashamed
about what happened with Chang.
Hell, I am too.
But locking
that little man up
is not gonna make our lives
any less crazy.
It will only make prison
crazier.
I guess you're right.
It's impossible
to keep the chaos
from your lives. We learned that
in that movie we saw
with all those dinosaurs.
Jurassic Park?
No, It's Complicated.
[CHANG SCREAMING]
Okay, okay. Time out, okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to you, you,
Officer Baby.
OFFICER: Let's go, buddy.
CHANG: No!
You're coming with me.
CHANG: No! No!
[♪♪♪]
Britta?
What? You guys want me
to ruin something for you?
Come on,
you're being dramatic.
We asked Lukka a few questions
after what you said.
He told us about his time
in the army
and the things he did...
I'm never gonna get those
images out of my head.
If I go to Balkans, I'm bringing
some serious cheat codes.
Why didn't you tell us
sooner?
I didn't wanna be the one
to ruin another guy
for you guys.
There's a difference
between telling us a guy
likes nipple play
and telling us a guy
makes hats out of babies.
The reason this happened
is because we've been
riding you hard lately.
How about we promise
to go easier on you,
if you promise not to tell us
about guys you're dating
unless they've committed
genocide?
Or if they're left-handed.
Wanna know. I'm making a chart.
Deal.
[♪♪♪]
I guess I ruined game night.
I tend to ruin stuff.
Come on.
You do not.
Wanna watch Catfish?
That movie
where the guy flirts
with the girl online,
but it turns out
that it's a fat, old woman?
Oh. Sorry.
It's cool.
Maybe it's about catfish.
[♪♪♪]
Well, this was fun.