[♪♪]
JEFF [NARRATING]:
It was my friend
Abed's birthday.
I had met Abed at community
college two years earlier.
His obsession with pop culture
had always alienated him.
He'd quote movies,
pretend life was a TV show.
He watched Cougar Town.
It was as if he didn't
want people to like him.
Then this year,
around Christmas,
he had some kind of,
I don't know, mental episode,
saying people were made
of clay, stuff like that.
He seemed okay since,
but when I asked if he'd like
anything for his birthday,
he told me
we should have dinner,
he and I,
for an important conversation.
It made me nervous.
The restaurant
wasn't his style at all.
There were cloth napkins,
no TVs.
Abed liked chicken fingers,
video games, Quentin Tarantino.
[PIANO PLAYING]
Babysitting him
through a full meal
at a restaurant
for grown-ups?
I just wasn't up for it.
But I loved Abed.
Everyone did.
So I had come there
with a plan of my own.
Hey, uh, could I get
a Macallan, neat?
Jeffrey.
Buddy.
I like your sweater.
Did it come
with a golden retriever?
[LAUGHS]
You look good too.
I would like a, um,
spritzer if possible.
Abed was being weird.
And by that,
I mean he wasn't being weird.
He was hugging, smiling,
making eye contact,
and in 30 seconds, he hadn't
made a reference to anything.
I had come in worried about
him, thinking he needed help.
But seeing him like this
made me more worried
than ever.
Get it? Like Pulp Fiction.
A wallet that says
"bad mother--"
Table's ready.
Actually, I had an idea.
I saw a very cool
burger place just a few--
Nonsense. I didn't come
downtown for burgers.
Come, come.
Uh, I'll be right there.
Hey, we're running
a bit late.
No big deal,
just a small speed bump.
BRITTA:
Well, hurry up. We're waiting.
ALL:
Surprise!
Guys, no.
They're running late.
Aw.
BRITTA:
Jeff says there's some kind
of speed bump.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Pierce, nobody can hear you.
Well, I'm hot, and my balls
are touching a zipper.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST
IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up, dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪
Can you imagine
the expression
on Abed's face
when he walks in?
PIERCE:
Of course I can imagine it.
It's always the same.
Yeah, but he's gonna say "cool"
at least five times.
It's great of Jeff
to put this together.
I'm not jealous.
Hmm?
Oh, cool,
someone got him a briefcase,
like in the movie.
What's in it?
Hey, don't touch that.
It's from Jeff. He says nobody
but Abed can open it.
Why? What's in it?
[♪♪]
What,
I have 3D vision now?
Yes, you do.
You don't know me.
Everybody be patient
and don't mess with anything.
I'm responsible for this diner
when my boss isn't around.
She will not stop
bragging about that.
I know.
PIERCE:
Has anyone seen this film?
Am I the hero
or love interest?
Pulp Fiction?
I saw it on an airplane. Cute.
It's a 30-minute film
about a group of friends
who like cheeseburgers,
dancing and the Bible.
[♪♪]
Jeff's not better than me.
Hmm?
I said, hmm.
Boy, is this menu stuffy.
I don't know about you,
but I'd rather have a nice--
Rillettes de Saumon,
to start,
I think, and, oh, the squab.
Very good.
They don't have quail.
Good to know. Salad.
WAITER:
Excellent choice.
Yeah, I nailed it.
Um, you forgot this
in the bar.
Ah, so I did. I'm sorry.
What a thoughtful gift,
Jeff.
I really was a man
of singular taste.
Was?
Abed, what's going on?
Why are you dressed
like Mr. Rogers,
talking like Frasier?
Oh, where to begin?
I mentioned my fondness for
a program called Cougar Town.
Here and there.
I even started a Cougar Town
fan club on Facebook.
Not to accomplish anything,
mind you.
Simply to express my love
for the show.
It ended up being quite large,
this fan club.
And one morning,
I think maybe early March,
I got this Facebook message.
A very nice message
from the people
who make Cougar Town.
Looking for work?
[LAUGHS]
No, thanking me, Jeff.
You know, for support
I generated for the show.
And in the last paragraph,
they said,
"You could come
visit the set."
Just like that.
Well, that's cool of them.
I guess that kind
of makes them
the Pulp Fictions of people.
How great was that movie?
So I sold my action figures
and bought a ticket
to Los Angeles.
Wait, you went? When?
Over spring break.
What could I do? Two days
after I got that invitation,
I was on the set of Cougar Town.
Cougar Town.
Want me to take it seriously,
stop saying its name.
You laugh, Jeff,
but the people were wonderful,
not just the actors,
but the crew. Everyone.
There must have been
200 people,
each with a specific
function,
but all dedicated
to a single purpose.
It was like a village
or a living thing.
I'm talking to the director
and he says,
"Jump into the background."
I say,
"Jump into the background
of what exactly?"
He says,
"Background of this scene.
Walk through it.
Walk through Cougar Town."
[PHONE BUZZES]
Thank you.
Well, before I can react,
this girl stands me
behind this patio
where the actors
are doing their scene.
The girl says,
"When you hear 'action,'
walk from here to there."
I really started to panic,
because if I'm a person
that watches Cougar Town,
how can I be in Cougar Town?
The more I start thinking
about it,
the less any of it
makes sense.
I wanna run, but too late,
the director's
calling "action."
So before I take
my first step, I realize
that I have to stop
being someone
who's seen the show
and become a character
on the show.
Become a man
from Cougar Town.
You know, someone born there,
someone whose name is Chad.
I take my first step,
as a child,
learning to walk as Chad.
With each step,
it becomes easier.
I start remembering things
from Chad's life,
like his first kiss
under the big tree
at Cougar Town field,
playing soccer
at Cougar Town Junior High,
finding my first chest hair
in the shower,
my first apartment,
my first true love
falling for my best friend,
birthdays, weddings,
car crashes, taxes,
playing charades
at Thanksgiving.
Chad had lived, Jeff.
You know, Chad had lived
more than Abed.
And then they called "cut"
and the scene was over.
But I wasn't ready
to stop being Chad,
so I said to the director,
"One more take?"
But they were already
moving on.
Courteney had nailed it.
My lips started trembling
and my hands and my feet
went numb,
my knees buckled,
and as I fell
to the floor...
I pooped my pants.
I did.
Because the truth is, Jeff,
I had been Chad,
and Chad was dead.
But as Abed,
I was still alive,
so someone helped me up.
Wardrobe lady came.
She gave me new pants.
I thanked everyone,
I apologized,
and then I got on a bus
and went straight
to the airport.
Um... Your food's
getting cold.
Oh. How silly of me.
[♪♪]
Hmm.
Wondering if Abed's
new best friend
also got him
the best gift?
I got Abed the best gift.
I'd tell you what it is,
but it's an even cooler secret.
Britta, you promised
that this private party
would be done by 8. You're doing
this during peak business hours
for nostalgic-themed diners.
Has that been researched?
It has.
Frightened by the evening news,
many seek
the comforting foods
and music
of a pre-racial America.
Sorry, Brian.
They're a little late.
I'll give you all of my tips
from my next shift.
Oh, your tips.
[SCOFFS]
All your tips?
Wait, wait, all of them?
Like, all the tips
the customers leave for you?
Wow. Is there any way we can
spread that over two years
so I don't get slammed
on my taxes?
Oh, my goodness.
I know.
Everyone hates Britta.
Mm-hm.
[PHONE BUZZES]
You know the real point
of that story.
I don't,
but that's okay. Chew.
The point is,
I'd been a fool.
No. Everybody poops
their pants.
I was a fool long
before that.
I look back and think,
"Who was that?
Why did he care
about things?"
Yeah. Who needs Cougar Town?
Who needs any pop culture?
TV, movies,
to hell with all of it.
You know what I was, Jeff?
I was that wallet.
On the surface, a reference
to cinematic drivel,
but on the inside, empty.
But you love Tarantino.
No, no, not anymore.
That's why I wanted
to have dinner.
First birthday
of my new life.
The wallet's cute,
but I'd like to exchange it.
I'm not leaving here until
you've given me
my first real conversation.
[♪♪]
Yay.
ABED:
Mm.
Okay, you wanna have
a real conversation?
Here's as real as I get
under the circumstances.
It's nice you've learned
to dial back your love of TV.
But I'd like you
to have a milkshake with me.
But before you do,
remember how much you enjoy
Pulp Fiction.
Now, that's as far
as I can go.
I'm really
tilting the bean can here.
Pulp Fiction, milkshakes,
bean cans?
Listen to how we talk.
We're like robots exchanging
catchphrases and references.
Pointing that out counts
as a real conversation?
Fake people are talking
about how fake the world is
right now.
So start
our real conversation.
I don't believe
there's such a thing.
Conversation was invented
by humans
to conceal reality.
We use it to sweet-talk
our way
around natural selection.
You know who has
real conversations? Ants.
They talk by vomiting chemicals
into each others' mouths.
They get right down
to brass tacks.
Bleh. "Which way's
the picnic?"
Bleh. "That way."
Humans are more evolved.
We lie.
Not all the time.
That's a lie.
We don't lie when we're alone.
Biggest lie ever.
Nine out of 10 lies occur six
inches from the bathroom mirror.
We do most
of our lying alone.
How's it possible
to lie alone?
You call a phone-sex line.
Lying to yourself.
That's just being honest
with a stranger.
What if you're dishonest
about why?
What if you're
a good-looking guy
and tells them
he weighs 400 pounds
just so he can hear a woman say
she's attracted to him anyway?
I don't believe that happens.
Wrong. That's me.
I did that last week.
What? Why pay a woman
to think you're fat?
Because I'm scared
that if I were overweight
that no one would like me.
[PHONE BUZZING]
God, that feels good
to admit.
[CHUCKLES]
Abed, the point being--
[PHONE BUZZES]
[GRUNTS]
The point being,
you don't have to worry
about being normal
or real or whatever
this is tonight.
The world is a sick place
full of sick, sick people.
[SIGHS]
Can I tell you something
I've never told anyone else?
Yes.
[♪♪]
It's gotta be so cool,
whatever he got him.
You know what I'm saying.
Winger's a man of means.
He's with your boy right now,
having a fancy dinner.
Baby chickens,
Diamond forks,
brand-name sodas.
Then he's gonna
bring him back here,
give him whatever's in there,
and that's that.
Troy who?
[MOUTHING]
Open. Open.
Is that
what I think it is?
It is.
CHANG:
Certificate of authenticity.
He must've got it on eBay
or something.
Jeff got Abed
the actual briefcase
from the movie
Pulp Fiction.
[WHIMPERS]
BRITTA: What are you guys doing?
Chang made me. He seduced me
with his dark Chinese powers.
Why do you leave him
alone with me?
I put my job on the line
for this stupid party
and the least you can do
is not ruin it.
No! No!
Huh? Aw.
BRITTA:
Aw.
Dude, I know I'm preaching
to the choir, but...
you are a bad friend.
I'll kill you!
What?
[YELLING]
[EASY-LISTENING MUSIC
PLAYING ON JUKEBOX]
[ANNIE AND SHIRLEY SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
And I said,
"No, that's a girl's costume."
And my mom said,
"Indian boys have long hair
and braids too."
There was only 45 minutes left
to trick-or-treat,
so what could I do?
I put the damn thing on
and I went door-to-door.
And everyone was going,
"Oh, what a pretty
little girl."
And by the third house,
I stopped correcting them.
I mean,
why draw attention to it?
And, honestly, once the shame
and the fear wore off...
I was just glad
they thought I was pretty.
God, this is incredible.
I mean, to be able
to talk this openly.
I mean, why can't people
be like this?
I mean, what's wrong
with this world?
What do you want?
So this is what you're doing
while we wait.
Go home, Pierce.
The party's canceled.
Pretty gay, man.
Pretty gay.
Why is Pierce dressed as
the gimp from Pulp Fiction?
Ah, pfft.
The wallet, milkshakes.
Did you set up a surprise
Pulp Fiction birthday party?
At the Greasy Fork,
but it doesn't matter now.
What matters is this.
Talking.
It everything okay?
Yes. Just the check, please.
WAITER: Oh.
I'm sorry.
So you're ending early?
In My Dinner with Andre--
Check, check, check. Bye.
Abed?
Mm-hm?
What's My Dinner with Andre?
It's just a movie
about, uh,
two guys talking
at a restaurant.
So this wasn't
a real conversation?
You were doing another movie?
A movie about
a real conversation.
Did you poop your pants
on the set of Cougar Town?
That shouldn't matter.
This is why
we don't hang out!
Thanks for getting me fired.
The party's over.
Cool, cool, cool.
JEFF: Yeah, it is.
Do you guys know where Abed's
really cool present is?
Because I'm returning it.
TROY:
Um-- It's back at the diner.
It's fine. It probably just
needs some detailing.
[♪♪]
Man, I really wish
you two got along better.
Oh, no-no juice.
Oh, that's good
no-no juice.
I'll give you $1200
for the damages
if you promise
to give Britta her job back.
Eight hundred
and she stays fired.
Deal.
Annie told me
about the briefcase.
Thank you.
What a waste.
Not really.
Buy it from Willy's Authentic
Cinema Treasures on eBay?
Yep.
Yeah, Willy exaggerates.
I got Indiana Jones'
real whip from him.
He moves 70 of those a year.
Good. Thought I flushed money
down the toilet.
Great to know the real
Pulp Fiction briefcase
is safe somewhere.
You're mad at me.
I spent a week planning
a party to make you happy.
And then I bailed
on the party and ruined it
just to make you happy.
While I was wasting time
trying to make you happy,
you were making yourself happy
all over everyone else
by doing yet another
stupid movie spoof.
I prefer the term "homage."
It wasn't about
making me happy.
My Dinner with Andre
is about a guy
who has an unexpectedly
enjoyable evening
with a weird friend
he's been avoiding lately.
You think
I've been avoiding you?
You and I hung out more
last year.
It makes sense.
Everyone else is growing
and changing,
and that's really
my jam.
[♪♪]
I'm more fast-blinking,
stoic,
removed,
uncomfortably self-aware type.
Like Data or Johnny 5
or Mork
or HAL or K.I.T.T. or K9
or Woodstock and/or Snoopy.
Spock goes without saying.
I don't need you
to grow or change.
And take it from someone
who just had
a meaningless one,
sometimes emotional
breakthroughs are overrated.
And, seriously,
keep a tight, heavy lid
on the little
Indian girl story.
Sure.
Tight, heavy lid.
Cool. THL.
Still friends?
Nobody paid for dinner
at the restaurant,
and I do not have
this kind of money.
[ERIK SATIE'S
"GYMNOPÉDIE NO. 1" PLAYS]
JEFF [NARRATING]:
I went back to pay the bill.
The restaurant was closed.
ALL:
Surprise!
Surprise.
It was Abed's idea.
The group had stayed behind
to salvage the party.
The waiter felt bad
for spilling the beans
about Abed's homage,
so he let us stay.
As parties go, it was quiet,
dark and a little lame.
We'd had better parties
and we'd had worse parties.
[NO AUDIO]
But I doubt
I'll ever forget
my Dinner with Andre
dinner with Abed.
[♪♪]
Thanks.
Abed, please, allow me.
Okay. Thanks.
ABED:
Let me see.
Mm. That's not good.
[SOBBING]
They said "market price."
What market
are you shopping at?
[SOBBING]
I'm going to run.
Me too.
Okay.
On three.
One.
Two.
Three.