PELTON [OVER PA]:
Don't forget, Greendale.
It's the last day
to sign up
for a spring
semester elective.
Horseback riding,
waterskiing, fencing.
Those are just a few classes
we can afford to offer
if enough people
pay to learn hopscotch.
Oh, they've got a class
on jokes.
Don't take that. I dropped it
after the lesson on setups.
The professor is so old...
So many classes.
I don't know what to choose.
I'll give you the advice
my father gave me
the night
I lost my virginity.
"Just pick one.
They all cost the same."
You could take "The Actor
Inside" with me and Troy.
How'd you get dragged
into that one?
Our dance teacher
encourages us
to take acting to tap
into our emotions,
so Troy and I both decided
to take it together.
Hm. Foosball was full?
On the wait list.
Don't give up.
I was on the wait list
for this class
for a year and I got in.
"Who Indeed:
A Critical Analysis
of Television's
Who's the Boss? "
The professor is the author.
We got him?
I know.
So, what are you taking,
Jeff?
While you are expanding
your minds and souls,
I'll be expanding my liver
in Italian Wine Tasting.
[SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
I'm taking that one too.
How do you say "ha, ha"
in Italian?
I'll look it up.
Come on, it'll be fun.
I can give you pointers.
I was a lawyer at
a top-tier law firm.
When I wasn't shielding
the wealthy,
I was drinking
their finest wines.
You have your own wine cellar?
Pierce does.
And it's "ha, ha."
Anyone can have a cellar.
It's what's in it.
Pierce's has a special gym
with swings and saddles.
Uh, we don't-- We don't discuss
the special gym.
MAN [OVER PA]:
Attention, please.
All elective forms must be in
by the end of the day.
PELTON [OVER PA]:
Oh, nice job, Manuel.
And good news,
there's still plenty of room
in my PA
Announcements class.
Just 10 bucks an hour.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
You're taking this too?
Hell, yeah.
You got drunk ladies,
fancy bathrooms
and a room full
of free coats.
Sorry I'm late, man.
I brought you a present.
Oh. From before
your chin dimple filled in.
Uh, excuse me.
So sorry.
Hm.
Whoa.
Who is the dumpling
with the nice Asian pair?
That's the first time sexism
made me hungry,
but she is something.
I fear I may have
to let her see me nude.
I might have to take
a shot myself.
[LAUGHS]
What's funny?
Why would a woman
want a Plymouth on blocks
when she could have a Testarossa
with a six-speed stick?
Because my stick
is ribbed for her pleasure.
I think those are wrinkles.
Let that breathe.
[SNIFFS]
Lingering scent, full body,
perfect nose.
Very nice wine.
I was talking about you.
Jeff Winger.
Wu Mei Hong Long.
Oh, what a lovely name
for a lovely--
Uh-- Not interested.
Please take weird haircut,
stupid grin,
and go sniff
another dog's ass.
Heh, heh.
The red dragon ordered
a Number 37 with a side
of pork-fried snap.
[LAUGHS]
When you get up close,
she's very homely.
This is gonna be fun.
I can't wait till
we choose stage names.
Which do you think
is better,
Trevor St. McGoodbody
or David?
Don't think you have
to worry about that.
This is about introspection.
TROY:
Drag.
Less of a drag.
MAN:
Quiet!
Form a trust circle around me
and sit on the floor.
BRITTA: A trust circle?
It's just a circle.
It's a circle. Sit down.
Acting is revealing,
expression.
When we release pain,
we become visible to each other,
and that is an actor's job.
That and, you know,
pretending to be other people.
Let's start with you.
Access and share with us
a profoundly deep
and painful memory.
I'm on the playground.
Stop taunting me.
[GASPING]
I just want to go
on the swings!
Good. Early childhood
is a treasure trove of pain.
That happened this morning.
You're up.
Me? Um...
I don't think...
I don't want you to think.
Feel. Go back.
Dig in, emotilize.
Something hurt you.
Um...
I was captain of
my high school football team.
[STUDENTS GROAN]
It was very hard
being popular.
MAN:
What a loser.
GARRITY:
Okay, great. Next person.
I've always felt
somehow ignored,
almost invisible.
Every time I go to say
something, somebody--
My uncle put his finger
in my no-no.
[STUDENTS GASP]
WOMAN:
What? Oh, my God.
This. This is where
acting begins.
[♪♪♪]
Welcome to A Critical Analysis
of Who's the Boss?
I am Professor
Peter Sheffield,
and I'd like to begin
with a simple question:
Who was the boss?
[STUDENTS CHUCKLING]
Yes.
Angela.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, well, class dismissed.
[STUDENTS LAUGHING]
No, calm down. Calm down.
I'm sorry, um, Mr...?
Abed.
The answer is not quite
that simple, Mr. Abed.
Few are.
Now, if everyone could please
turn to Page 12 in my book.
MAN:
Ahem, loser.
You have to finish
that by tomorrow?
Yeah,
but it's a page-turner.
I'm on the chapter
where
he traces Tony Micelli's
genealogy to Caesar.
Better than wine tasting
with Pierce.
Refused pinot noir,
thought it was French
for "black penis."
And he's late, again.
It's not your fault.
[MOUTHING]
Thank you.
He'll be here.
He wouldn't miss a chance
to say something offensive.
Man's gonna run out of ways
to shock people.
Everybody, this is Wu Mei,
and we're getting married.
[♪♪♪]
But it's not gonna be today.
So you're getting married
to that beautiful young thing?
Well, uh, stranger things
have happened.
No. No, they haven't.
You said you guys
just met?
Yesterday after
wine tasting class
I mentioned that
her breasts were larger
than most Asian women,
and we just got to talking.
Turns out Pierce
has been to China many times.
To get fireworks
too dangerous for Mexico.
PIERCE:
No. I go to visit my factory.
Hawthorne Wipes are the
number-one towelette in Asia.
After a few minutes,
we both just knew we were
meant to be together forever.
Or at least until
she gets heavy.
And now we must leave you.
Many plans to make.
Yes, yes, big plans.
Well, what are we gonna do?
Plan an engagement party.
You out of your mind?
This is a scam.
She's after his money
or a green card.
They seem to like
each other.
Pierce married three
of his wives after a month.
Maybe he's just a romantic.
Not that you would
understand romance.
Don't preach to me
about romance.
I had a three-way
in a hot air balloon.
Fine.
Guess I'll do it myself.
Ready to go?
Mm-hm.
Boy, he seems
really worked up.
Hey, don't take on his pain.
Tend your own garden.
I'll see you in class.
What's going on?
Oh, um...
I didn't have
a painful experience
to share in acting class,
so I said my uncle
tried to touch my butt.
Britta's attracted to pain.
Helps her pretend to be healthy.
Really?
Yeah.
I hadn't noticed.
Troy?
Hm?
Nothing good can come of this.
Yeah.
I'll have to think hard about
how to defuse the situation.
No, Uncle Lucius,
I don't wanna play
in the laundry room!
[SOBBING]
My emotions! My emotions!
MAN: That was really beautiful.
Actors dismissed.
Uh, for homework,
drink a glass of cognac
in a bathtub.
Troy, I feel like I'm seeing
a whole different side of you.
There's just
so much darkness.
And my soul is darkening,
and my heart is mad
at my kidneys, and...
My mouth...
See you tomorrow.
[♪♪♪]
Um, hello.
Oh, hi.
I'm glad you could come.
Please sit.
Okay.
I felt like we got off
on the wrong foot,
and I wanted to offer you
my other foot.
First, let me say
how happy I am for you both.
Your parents must be
so excited.
Are they coming to the wedding?
Oh, they would not miss it.
My mother will make
the customary shark's fin soup,
and my father will get drunk and
make bad impression of Borat.
Oh, so your parents don't mind
having a son-in-law
roughly their age?
No. Pierce is a beautiful,
wise man,
very gentle soul.
Let me tell you that
I am a lawyer,
so if you need
any help at all,
navigating the whole green card,
immigration hassle...
I am dual citizen already.
Oh. If you'd like me
to look at the prenup...
I assume you have one.
Yes, but my father's lawyers
will take care of this.
After all, we must protect
our family fortune.
Hm. Now I'm stumped.
Excuse me?
Uh... It was...
That means it was very nice
talking to you.
Oh. Okay, if you say so.
Okay. Bye.
Okay, goodbye.
Why were you grilling her?
I'm gonna bust
into her apartment.
Do you have any
grappling hooks?
Maybe Pierce
found his soul mate.
How can you say those things
without irony?
That's why they call me
irony-free Annie.
Mm, trust me,
that's not what they call you.
[♪♪♪]
Yes? Oh.
Mr. Abed.
What can I do for you?
I finished your book,
professor.
I've been watching
Who's the Boss?
There's something
you overlooked.
Mr. Abed,
will you look at my wall?
Mm-hm.
What do you see?
Photographs.
Of what?
You.
With whom?
Tony Danza, Judith Light,
Alyssa Milano,
Who's the Boss caterer
Gordon "Giddy-up" Galligan.
I have studied this show,
Mr Abed.
I am not a fan,
I am not a groupie,
I am an academic.
When I ask the question,
"Who's the boss?"
it is a rhetorical question.
When I ask the question beyond
the question,
"What is a boss?"...
I really think it's Angela,
because if it's a boss
you're looking at...
Enough!
I would like you to leave.
My mind is open.
Open as the door
to Mona's bedroom.
It's a shame yours isn't.
I beg your pardon?
You know,
I just got a wonderful idea.
Why don't you teach
the next class?
That way you can share
your open mind with everybody.
Cool. Cool, cool, cool.
Pew!
I couldn't be more touched
you threw us
an engagement party.
You said if we didn't,
you'd slash our tires.
Ha, ha, ha. She is funny.
Like Oprah.
Oprah's not a comedienne.
No, you are funny,
and you are like Oprah.
Heh, heh, heh. Yeah.
What?
WU MEI: Thank you.
Pierce.
I'd like to offer
sincere congratulations.
It's hard to find people
you can stand,
let alone someone
willing to stomach
your imminent dementia
and present incontinence.
Thank you, Jeff.
I just hope she can satisfy me.
I'm like an insatiable baboon
in the bedroom.
Don't sell yourself short.
You're a baboon everywhere.
TROY:
Seems like yesterday me and
Abed dined and ditched here.
[CHUCKLES]
[PIANO PLAYING]
Here, hold this.
Bah. What is this?
I carry spare apps
in case the staff's racist.
Where's a napkin?
Here you go.
Oh, thanks.
Check that out.
Hats off to Pierce
and the hot red dragon.
Why do you keep calling
her that?
"Hong Long" means
"red dragon."
That's her middle name.
In China, they put
the last name first.
I mean,
they're nuts over there.
Thank you all for coming.
I know it seems fast,
but when you find
the right person, you know.
I know because I've found
the right person seven times.
So the drinks are on me,
but stick to the crappy stuff.
I don't wanna get cornholed
on the bar tab.
Pierce, you can't just
throw around a term like that.
Cornhole. Cornhole.
Cornhole.
Pierce, Troy was molested.
Cool.
Troy, we didn't know.
Troy, do you need me
to recommend a support group?
Hey, he's not a victim.
You're a survivor.
Yeah, about that.
I wasn't so much "molested"
as much as I "made it up."
What?
We're gonna laugh so hard
about this later.
JEFF:
I'd like to propose a toast.
Wu Mei Hong Long, better known
as Mei Hong Long Wu,
is not only
not a Greendale student,
she works
for Red Dragon Wipes,
the number-two wipe in Asia,
currently attempting
a takeover of Hawthorne Wipes.
So please,
raise your glasses,
to saving Pierce from
the clutches of a corporate spy.
And to me for being
attractive enough
to get a girl like her
under normal circumstances.
Very impressive, Veronica Mars.
You learned how to use Google.
And you learned to fight
your desire for me.
Oh, stick it. You suck.
Wait, wait, wait.
[RECORD SCRATCHES
OVER SPEAKER]
Record scratch app.
[♪♪♪]
Where'd everybody go?
Most people went home.
The rest went with Chang
to have a ketchup fight.
I better get back there before
he starts playing monkey drop.
Don't ask.
Oh, uh...
Do you wanna come?
Why would I wanna go
anywhere with Judas Winger?
You're mad?
You should thank me.
For what?
Ruining my relationship?
What relationship?
You just met the woman,
and the entire thing was a lie.
She was just using you
to get your company.
And I was just using her
to get her company in the sack.
People use each other,
Jeff.
It doesn't mean that there
aren't feelings that go with it.
I liked her.
She was busty.
I thought we had something.
I was trying to help you.
I think what you were
trying to do
is prove that
no woman could want me.
You're here.
Look, Britta,
I'm really sorry.
Troy, kissing you was a mistake.
It will never happen again.
Good.
Before my ex-boyfriend Pablo
was arrested for forging
church relics,
he accused me
of only being attracted
to a certain kind of guy.
It was hard
to understand him, though.
He was huffed up
on paint thinners.
Well, maybe someday you'll fall
for someone who's healthy.
Someone who,
other than his irrational fear
of automatic toilets,
is normal.
Who would like to begin
today?
I would.
With a confession.
My uncle never stuck
his finger in my plop-plop.
[STUDENTS GASPING]
I know,
I'm bummed about it too.
I'm sorry.
I wanna be interesting.
I wanna fit in with you guys.
I wanna be able to be
an actor.
The pain of not having
enough pain
is still pain, young man.
That may sound like
an easy resolution, but...
we're not writers.
We're actors.
Story doesn't matter here.
All that matters
is our time...
in the spotlight.
And so, by all known definitions
of the word "boss,"
i.e., one with authority
over another,
in nine of 11
possible fields
in which one might teach,
employ, guide,
oversee,
and-or hold dominion,
the empirically
provable answer
to the question
"who's the boss?" is...
[CLOCK TICKING]
Angela Bower.
[STUDENTS MURMURING]
Class dismissed.
Class dismissed!
There's a path you take
and a path untaken.
The choice is up to you,
my friend.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
I wonder why Jeff and Abed
didn't show.
PIERCE:
I don't know about Abed,
but I'm sure Jeff just
found another life to destroy.
You thinking
about studying acting?
I'm auditioning
for Garrity's
all-black production
of Fiddler on the Roof.
It's called Fiddla Please.
What's she doing here?
I asked her to come.
I was thinking maybe you two
were meant to be together.
You're both rude,
deceitful and racist,
and you both come
from moist-wipe dynasties.
I think having that much
in common
justifies at least one
real date.
[SIGHS]
I guess we could go to dinner.
You're paying.
You're dressing slutty.
Fine.
How about Mexican?
How about Thai?
They're like
Chinese Mexicans.
Heh. So true.
Hm.
[♪♪♪]
♪ It's hard to be Jewish
It's hard to be Jewish ♪
In Russia, yo ♪
♪ It's hard to be Jewish
It's hard to be Jewish ♪
♪ Hard to be Jewish
In Russia, yo ♪
♪ Bagels and lox
Diamond shops ♪
♪ It's hard to be Jewish
In Russia, yo ♪
♪ Hard to be Jewish
Hard to be Jewish ♪
In Russia, yo ♪♪
Someone drop
an Old Testament beat.
[BEATBOXING]
Dreidels.