FAT NEIL:
No!
[FAT NEIL SCREAMING]
MAN:
Stay calm, everybody!
FAT NEIL:
No, no, no!
MIKE:
You can't outrun me.
I see you, fat-ass!
FAT NEIL:
No, don't shoot me!
[LAUGHING]
Guys, please.
Okay, I don't even have a gun.
Isn't this
against the rules?
There's only one rule,
Fat Neil.
The prize goes
to the last man standing.
WOMAN:
So to speak.
[GUNSHOTS]
[MEN GROAN]
If you were a dude, you'd
have my fist up your balls.
[♪♪♪]
Thank you, Annie.
Kick their guns to me.
Kick, don't reach. Hey.
Christina Reachy,
I said kick.
Annie, take it easy.
You gotta learn to trust people.
[♪♪♪]
Can't you leave me
with a little something?
We're friends, Annie,
remember?
We played Dungeons
&amp; Dragons together.
That was a game.
[♪♪♪]
This is paintball.
[GUNSHOT]
[♪♪♪]
PELTON:
Let's gather round.
Okay, a couple of announcements.
I wanna thank Pistol Patty's
Cowboy Creamery
for sponsoring
our end-of-the-year picnic.
Now, free ice cream
and that one guy
having a heart attack
aren't the only
surprises today.
We're gonna end this year
with a quick game
of Paintball Assassin.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Now, last year's big mistake
was way too valuable a prize.
And I've been assured, huh,
that this year
will be different.
So take it away,
Pistol Patty.
PATTY:
Howdy, folks.
There's only one rule:
Last man standing gets
the prize. There's your guns.
[CROWD MURMURING]
And here's the prize:
One hundred thousand
dollars cash.
Go nuts!
[AIR HORN TOOTING]
[CROWD YELLING]
Ah!
[RATTLING]
[♪♪♪]
I heard you never shoot
an unarmed man.
Whoever started that rumor
didn't eat my beans.
Then I guess it's lucky for me
I'm not unarmed.
Seeing as I'm...
eating your beans.
Jeff wants to see you.
Yeah? And I want pants.
A lot of people
want a lot of things.
It won't hurt
to hear him out.
We got a good spot
in the library.
As safe as you are here,
you'll be safer with us.
MAN 1:
I see you! There they go!
[JEFF &amp; CHANG SCREAMING]
[GUNFIRE]
Math Club's gotten better
since last year.
They were practicing while
the rest of us went on dates.
[♪♪♪]
Hold on. I have a plan.
Math Club?
MAN 1: Yeah?
I'm Asian. You guys Asian?
That's pretty
racist, man.
That wasn't a no.
I'm coming over.
Don't shoot me, shoot him.
He's white and he's out of ammo.
Crap.
[♪♪♪]
[GUNSHOTS]
MAN 1:
Don't shoot!
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
CHANG: See you, Abed.
JEFF: Shoot Chang!
He defected to the Math Club.
CHANG: Math rules!
Ahh.
Forget it.
Just a waste of ammo.
Let's go grab their paint.
Cool.
Yeah, I'm much safer
with you guys.
Milady.
What do you want, Jeff?
Yikes. Well,
what do we all want?
Ammo.
How much you got left?
A hundred thousand dollars
worth.
We're running low too.
JEFF: Shut up, Abed.
What have you heard
about Pierce?
Hear he's still alive,
near the cafeteria.
I hear he has more paint
than a French kindergarten.
Are you proposing
we join him?
I'm proposing
his ammo joins us.
You haven't changed.
You think Pierce has?
The guy's been
a jerk all year.
He's a jerk
because we exclude him.
We exclude him
because he's a jerk.
Last I checked, you were
the last feeling sorry about it.
[♪♪♪]
I'm waiting for you guys
to come around.
Likewise.
[GUNSHOTS]
[PAVEL SCREAMING]
I am dead, bro. I'm dead.
[SPURS CLINKING]
Who wears spurs
in paintball?
[♪♪♪]
[SPURS CLINKING]
Who the hell are you?
The guy that's gonna win.
[♪♪♪]
Come on!
Does that guy
even go to this school?
He's really good-looking.
Like network TV good-looking.
See how big
his guns were?
Just marry him.
Paintball is tough this year.
I agree.
[♪♪♪]
Careful, you can't hit
all three of us.
She won't have to.
[♪♪♪]
[COUGHING]
Hey, Troy.
Abed.
[♪♪♪]
I thought you were dead.
Guys.
Oh, right.
By the power
invested in us as deputies,
we now pronounce
you arrested.
What are you,
deputies of the stairwell?
Fort Hawthorne.
There's a bounty
on your head, my friend.
Pierce.
My forehead's
not that big, right?
Hm.
It's not small.
[♪♪♪]
JEFF:
You let Pierce boss you around
in exchange for paint pellets?
Actually, Jeff, he's been pretty
decent in this game so far.
He's created a safe zone
where people can rest,
eat and pump breast milk.
That sounds
very nice of him.
Beats standing
around waiting
to get picked off
by the Black Rider.
Are you talking about
the handsome blond cowboy
with the big guns?
Is that guy a student?
Who is he?
We call him the Black Rider.
But he's not riding anything.
Look, I don't
name people, Annie.
I'm a deputy. I deputize.
You have to surrender
your guns.
And your drugs.
Drugs.
[PIANO MUSIC PLAYING]
Ah.
My study group.
How long has it been?
Five hours.
Too long.
Welcome to Fort Hawthorne.
How is this
even possible?
It began
with a dream, Annie.
A dream and an impulse
to hide in the men's room.
I found that people were willing
to roll bullets under the door
just for the right
to take a dump.
By the way, for you guys,
taking a dump is on the house.
Or if you prefer,
relax and catch a show.
This is insane.
Don't worry, Jeff,
I've also got someone
more your speed.
Because you're gay.
I think I've seen enough,
and I'd like
my gun back now.
Only Hawthorne personnel can
carry weapons inside, Jeffrey.
All right, you got us here,
unarmed, at your mercy.
What do you want?
We'll discuss
over dinner.
You're famished.
Tonight, we feast.
The Twinkies
are wonderful tonight.
Give us some space,
Miguel.
What if I told you guys
I know where to find enough ammo
to end this
cowardly hiding out?
Split the prize
seven ways.
So send your goons
to get it.
PIERCE:
They'd never bring it back.
We trust each other,
we're a study group.
That's pretty warm and fuzzy
talk coming from you, Pierce.
You've acted like
a villain this year.
I have?
Yes.
You raped the Duquesne family.
Guys, Pierce is reaching out.
I'm not risking my butt
hauling ammo
for the guy that has
Vicky dancing for Twinkies.
She's a dance major, Jeff.
She loves Twinkies.
And if you ever took the time
to get to know her--
Look, uh...
Summer starts tomorrow.
For you guys,
it means pool parties,
dinners, one-night stands.
For me,
it means counting down
the days till next fall.
Before we go,
let me do this for you.
Let me bring us victory.
[♪♪♪]
Fine. Let's do it.
To the study group.
ALL:
Ah. More juice,
Miguel.
I hope we find this cache
of ammunition soon.
I need to pump.
Me too.
You talking about
peeing, right?
No.
Me neither.
Look, about Pierce,
I feel bad.
I shouldn't put
so much effort into--
It's okay.
I just think the study group
is my family, you know?
And if we start
picking and choosing--
Where do we stop?
I get it.
You're a good kid,
and I wanna do my part
to help you stay that way.
WOMAN:
Benjamin Chang,
for your betrayal
of the Cheerleaders' Alliance,
I sentence you
to pretendsies death.
Guys, you don't have
to do this.
I betrayed
the Math Club for you.
Ready.
Sorry I told Trish about Amber.
WOMAN: Aim--
Fire.
Holy crap.
Not cool, bitch.
Yeah, so you told me
at last year's tryouts.
Ah!
Leave the guns.
Whatev.
Who's there?
Can I join you?
ALL: No.
Okay.
[CLICKING]
I'm out. Give me your gun.
All right, be careful.
Cheerleaders rule!
[♪♪♪]
[GUN COCKS]
I'll take that.
Who are you?
I'm the bad guy.
Stop trying to fluster me
with your handsomeness.
You're creepy.
Why is your chest
getting all flushed?
It's a rash.
I'm allergic to beans.
Look, do you even
go to school here?
Sorry, I get paid
to shoot paintballs, honey,
not the breeze.
Lame.
I'll hit you in the foot.
Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
[GUNSHOTS]
You're dry, sugar.
Hey.
ABED:
[♪♪♪]
I'll save you for last.
You won't get the chance.
Unh!
You okay?
I got a better look at him.
He's not that good-looking.
Didn't he shoot you?
He tried.
He's a bad shot too?
Man, what does this guy
have going for him?
Pierce loaded your gun
with blanks.
[GROANING]
No, don't shoot!
Why does this
keep happening?
And what kind of ice cream
company does this?
Where's the paint
from last year?
I hid it. So the school
doesn't get destroyed.
Too late.
Oh, hi, Jeff.
We ran into the Black Rider.
Dean, if you want this game
to end, we need firepower.
[SIGHS]
In there.
The key's in my shorts.
I can get it out,
I guess.
[♪♪♪]
Now, this is
more like it.
Okay, Black Rider,
now let's see who's attractive.
Dude,
you have a problem.
Ha, ha, ha. Oh, nice.
Whoa, where you going?
To have a conversation
with Pierce.
She's pretty awesome today.
[PIANO MUSIC PLAYING]
What happened?
Black Rider.
He wiped out
the whole fort.
Then why are you still here?
I can't go back out there,
this is the only life I know.
PIERCE:
Annie?
Is that you?
Did you get the ammo?
Yup.
Hey! What are you doing?
Why's Jeff's gun
loaded with blanks?
Was it?
[GUNFIRE]
[SCREAMING]
PIERCE:
Oh, come on, now. Hey, hey.
Oh. Okay. I get it.
So once again,
I'm the bad guy.
ALL:
Yes.
Well, he got to win
last year.
It's a game, Annie.
Fine.
It's a game.
Let's play.
Put it in your holster.
PIERCE: Come on, Annie.
You're my favorite,
I don't wanna beat you.
I don't want Jeff
to be the--
Put the gun in your holster
and let's play the game.
Right.
So you can shoot me
and play without me.
That's this group's
favorite thing.
We're always
nice to you, Pierce.
Wrong.
Three days ago,
I walked in on you guys
playing cards without me.
Three days ago.
We weren't playing cards,
we were voting.
And you weren't invited because
we were voting about you.
What?
We were taking a vote
on whether we'd invite you
back to the group next year.
Lucky for you,
it had to be unanimous.
There was one holdout.
One red card.
[♪♪♪]
Pick it up.
[SPURS CLINKING]
Black Rider.
It's Jeff Winger.
I know you've heard
of me by now.
BLACK RIDER:
No.
He's lying.
Look, if you're half the cool
cowboy you pretend to be,
you'll respect that we've got
a situation playing out here
and let us be
until it's settled.
BLACK RIDER:
Sure thing.
And once it's settled,
I'm taking out
everybody in this room.
Oh.
Starting with you, Mr. Insecure.
You think you're good-looking,
but you're not.
You're average.
You're just an average-looking
guy with a big chin.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
What's going on?
He's faking it.
BLACK RIDER: Something's wrong.
SHIRLEY: It's fake.
Last week he did it to get out
of letting me have gum.
He's old,
it could be real.
It's real. It is. Argh!
The gurgling's a nice touch.
You guys are terrible.
Eh, we warned you.
Buddy, are you all right?
You want me to call 911?
Sucker!
Son of a bitch, seriously?
Told you, dude.
I'm the best!
You're the worst.
I'm out of the group?
You're out of mine!
And I'm winning!
We've created a monster.
Let's not give ourselves
too much credit.
I'm out. Some old guy pretended
to have a heart attack.
Shot me in the gut.
I don't care,
that's your problem.
This school sucks.
Well, then why do you go here?
I wouldn't go to this toilet
with my big sister's toe.
I take a class online.
I was paid to be here
and win the game
so my boss
could keep his money.
You work for
the ice cream company?
Sweetie, this thing
is so much bigger
than you can even imagine.
I'm out of here,
I got Coldplay tickets.
Coldplay?
Too late, bean allergy,
you blew it.
CHANG:
Hello?
Anybody?
Does anyone have
an alliance I can join?
I'm really loyal.
[SCREAMING]
Am I out?
MAN 1:
In formation.
Blue Leader, standing by.
Blue Leader, stand by.
MAN 2:
Red 5, standing by.
MAN 3:
White Clones, standing by.
PATTY:
On your knees.
No Greendale student can be
allowed to win this game.
Initiate Plan B:
Operation Total Invasion.
Greendale students,
I understand you've unified
and intend
to draw this game out.
Well, if it's a war you want,
it's a war you shall lose.
Resistance is as pointless
as your degrees.
[♪♪♪]
Are we the Little Rascals?
I was.
I'm the dean,
stop shooting me!
We're gonna lose
this war and school.
This is it.
We're dying out here.
I had a dream it'd end this way.
Once I'm gone, I'm gone.
I'll see you in hell.
That's the tip of the iceberg.