♪ We're gonna fly
To school each morning ♪
♪ We're gonna smile
The entire time ♪
♪ We're gonna be more happy ♪
♪ We're gonna finally be fine ♪
♪ We're gonna get
More calm and normal ♪
♪ We're gonna fix
Our state of mind ♪
♪ We're gonna be less crazy ♪
ALL:
♪ We're gonna finally be fine ♪
♪ We're gonna stand holding
Hands in a brand new land ♪
♪ Far away from the borderline ♪
♪ We're gonna seem
Like a mainstream dream ♪
♪ And be appealing
To all mankind ♪
ALL:
♪ We're gonna have more fun
And be less weird ♪
♪ Than the first
Two years combined ♪
♪ And we're gonna live forever ♪
BOTH:
♪ We're gonna sleep together ♪
ALL:
♪ And we're gonna finally
Be sunny and shinily ♪
♪ We're gonna finally be fine ♪
ANNIE:
Jeff. Jeff?
Oh, sorry.
Uh, what was the question?
What are we gonna do
without Pierce
in the study group this year?
We'll figure it out.
Speaking of figuring
things out,
me and Abed
have an announcement.
Troy and I are
living together.
Oh, that's...
Oh, that's nice.
We're registered
at Linens 'n Things.
We have linens.
We want the things.
How you like me now,
bitches?
Dean,
you seem different.
You in a play?
Time to whip
this place into shape.
I'm gonna be a mean, lean,
deaning machine.
No more paintball,
no more spaceships,
no more trampolines,
and no more...
[METAL TINGING]
What is that?
It's probably the monkey
that lives in the vents.
I named him "Annie's Boobs,"
after Annie's boobs.
DEAN:
This is the kind
of national lampoonery
that is coming
to an end this year.
Homie don't dean this.
BRITTA:
Let's get to Biology on time.
I don't wanna be a screw-up.
Uh, Britta.
Damn it!
We're really doing this
without Pierce? So sad.
We've parted ways
with our closest,
oldest, craziest,
most racist, oldest,
elderly, crazy friend,
and he's not coming back.
I'm back.
[ALL CHEERING]
How was your summer?
Enlightful, Annie.
I underwent three months
of intensive soul-rezoning
at the Laser Lotus
Celebrity Center.
I stand before you a more highly
evolved Pierce Hawthorne,
one that can accept
that this table has a...
Has a sort of magic in it.
BOTH:
Aw.
[SIGHS]
I'd like to come back.
ANNIE: Yeah.
Damn it!
Oh, uh, sorry.
I had the frustrating
realization
that you can't come back,
you're not in Biology
and it's full.
Couldn't we take something else?
Surely we've evolved beyond
caring what class
we take together.
ANNIE:
Oh, yeah. Pierce!
I'll do you one better.
I think we've evolved beyond
reliance on a group at all.
Aren't we just
actual friends now,
no matter where we are?
What's magic
about this table?
It magically keeps our books
from falling on the floor.
Ah.
JEFF: The table's for studying,
but as friends,
we've evolved.
Let's use that first breath
of crisp, new,
super-evolved air
to declare proudly
and in one voice:
"Pierce,
we'll see you
when we see you."
Don't tell the monkey
I'm living here.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
Star-Burns,
I see you added a lizard
to your special hat
and sideburns.
Am I missing anything?
Yeah.
The human being
underneath it all,
but no one's interested
in that, are they?
No.
I hope we did the right
thing about Pierce.
He really seems
like he's changed.
That's what he wants you
to think.
Trust me.
We're better off.
Excluding Pierce is
what drove him crazy.
Wrong, being crazy
drove him excluded.
[WHINES]
What?
Cougar Town's been moved.
Mmm.
That's never a good sign.
Not cool, not cool.
It's coming back
in January.
Six seasons and a movie.
Oh.
This is intro to Biology.
I'm your professor,
Dr. Marshall Kane, PhD.
It took me 6205 hours
to get my degree,
and I know,
because I was only allowed
in the library
one hour per day at the San
Vicente Correctional Facility
while serving a sentence
of 25 to life.
Now, let's talk about
that word.
"Life."
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
Uh, sorry. It's a new phone.
Switching to vibrate.
Continue.
It's really great.
I stared at a crack in the
ground in my cell for years,
and one day,
something grew from it.
A single blade of grass.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATES]
[CHUCKLES]
Vibrates louder
than the ringer.
Gosh. You know what?
Turning it off.
Living thing,
growing from dead stone.
[CELL PHONE TUNE]
Get out!
JEFF: Oh, it's off, it's off.
Out!
I turned it off.
Fine. Okay, fine.
I'm leaving.
And don't bother coming back.
Seriously? Hey, dude,
Sean Penn called.
He says to dial it back.
Sean Penn's an actor who--
I know.
I've seen Milk.
Now get out.
Dude, learn to blend.
I will not tolerate
monkeys living on campus.
If I wanted
to run a monkey hotel,
I'd install a banana buffet.
I'd use vines as elevators,
and I'd put tail holes
in the bathrobes,
and I'd lower
all the shower knobs.
You've thought this through.
It's your turn.
Brainstorm.
Idea shower.
Spray your solutions
all over me.
We could seal all the vents
and then pump the ducts
with some kind of gas
that knocks out monkeys.
DEAN:
Monkey knockout gas!
That's the kind
of grounded, sensible thinking
I wanna see this year.
Catherine, who's next?
Vice Dean Laybourne
from Air-Conditioning Repair
School annex.
Vice Dean.
Dean. New suit, Dean?
New Dean, Vice Dean. New Dean.
I see that you
used school funds
to buy an espresso machine
for your faculty break room.
I don't recall being
consulted on that.
We don't consult you
on anything.
That's the problem.
The Air-Conditioning
Repair School annex
seems to think it's separate
from Greendale,
but it's an annex.
An appendage, on a body,
with a head,
and this head is saying
to this appendage,
"Whazup?"
What you say makes sense, Dean.
Tell you what.
You bring your head down
to my appendage tomorrow,
and I'll show you
"whazup."
I'll be there.
[CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHS]
[LAUGHS LOUDER]
I think I found something
that will help Abed.
Abed, did you know
that Cougar Town
is an American adaptation
of a 1990s British sitcom?
ABED:
Cougarton Abbey.
Just been around
Cougarton Chapel.
I'm having an awakening.
Come off it. You're having
a butchers at the choir boys.
[SITCOM LAUGHTER]
Better than nothing.
Thanks, Britta.
Can you believe that guy,
kicking me out of class
like that?
It's gonna be impossible
to find a science class
with six open spots.
Why do that?
I'm not in Biology anymore.
Neither is Pierce,
but you're both
still our friends.
We've evolved.
Right, Jeff?
Yes, we have.
We love each other.
ANNIE: Mmm-hmm.
We all go to the same school,
so, uh...
I guess I'll see ya
when I see ya.
PIERCE:
Hey, guess what.
I was on the wait list
for Biology,
somebody got
kicked out,
I am here to study!
ALL:
Yay!
All hail, Sir Eats-Alone.
Shut up, Leonard.
I heard about
your prescription socks.
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
Hope you don't mind,
Jeff,
got a new show,
only on Episode Six.
You guys got five minutes
to eat.
Time flies when you're studying
the science of life.
Time flies
when you joke
about movies that sound like
names for poops.
[ALL LAUGH]
The Remains of the Day.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Were you eavesdropping
on our study session?
I was eavesdropping
on your goof-off session,
you missed
the most obvious one.
No, I said
Green Mile.
Operation Dumbo Drop.
[ALL EXCLAIMING IN DISGUST]
Too clever by half,
Jeffrey.
All right,
I gotta go.
Thanks for
the five minutes.
Aw, Jeffrey.
The barrister's foreclosed
the Abbey.
Fancy a drink, then?
Oi, fetch us a Hemlock.
Um...
[CHOKES]
[AUDIENCE GASPING]
Um...
Britta?
Why did everyone
on Cougarton Abbey just die?
They only ran
six episodes.
That's the great thing
about British TV. Closure.
[SCREAMS]
No, no, no!
We'll find you
a new favorite show!
Come on, buddy.
You are human
tennis elbow.
You are a pizza burn on the roof
of the world's mouth.
You are the opposite of Batman.
You don't need them, man.
Exactly. I'll see 'em
when I see 'em.
Totally.
We should hang out
sometime. Grab a drink?
Sure.
Where are you living now?
The air vents
of the school. Shh!
I'm free, Jeff. Free!
I gotta get back
in that class.
Real Dean coming through...
Oh, my goodness, spacious!
Vice Dean...
Is this where Greendale's
money is going?
More accurately, Dean,
it's where Greendale's money
comes from.
Our air-conditioning program has
a job placement rate
five times higher than the rest
of your school combined.
Our alumni donations
comprise 80 percent
of your entire
school's budget.
And you want to know why
we think we deserve
[YELLING]
an espresso machine?
[YELPS]
Well, I guess I didn't know. I--
Then you never had to, Dean.
You could've lived the rest of
your life in blissful ignorance
and died a happy,
pansexual imp.
But you wanted
to feel power this year.
Well, now, you're going
to feel my power
as it surges downward from me,
straight through you,
from nostril to rectum,
now until the end of time.
And that's "whazup."
[WHIMPERS]
I forgot everything you said
before "rectum"!
[GASPS]
Who are these guys?
This is my legal team,
because I think it's time
we worked out
a new agreement.
He doesn't look
like a lawyer.
That's a barber.
Because I'm also sick
of that ridiculous goatee.
You look like a white
Lou Gossett Jr.
[DEAN SCREAMS]
You deserve
a bigger office.
Biggest office I ever had.
I'm here to apologize,
Dr. Kane,
and beg you for a seat
in Biology.
You wanna learn
about life?
Give up the phone.
You're asking me
for a bribe?
I can't be bought, man.
You feel me?
See,
prison was my walls.
But you put your walls up.
You, and your phone,
and your attitude,
and your
Fruit Loops cologne.
Your walls put up
so tight, man,
not even a blade of grass
could get through.
But even if it did,
you wouldn't appreciate it.
[SCOFFS]
That's why you can't
come back to my class.
What's your problem
with me, man?
And don't act like it's not
about me specifically,
because you've been in--
[GASPS]
Busted!
Hey!
Take it easy, Winger.
Everything okay?
It is now that I have this.
This is my ticket
to getting back in the group.
Hey! Hey!
Eh!
I wanna be
in the group so bad!
All right, let's smoke 'em
and choke 'em.
No! No! No, no!
[WHOOSHING]
Uh-oh.
What is that?
Monkey gas!
JEFF:
Monkey gas?
Oh, my God!
Abed?
All your friends
are here.
They wanna talk to you.
How's this different
from the way he always is?
This'd be a great time
to baptize him.
Abed, maybe this can be
your new favorite show.
It's a British
sci-fi series
that's been on the air
since 1962.
Britta, you've done enough.
Why not start
a ruiners' club?
Wait,
you'd probably ruin it.
I'd be doing
a good job
because it's
a ruiners' club.
You ruined my analogy.
ANNIE:
Guys, look!
Blimey, Inspector!
Where have we
wound up this time?
Not where, Constable,
but when.
Inspector, look out!
Blorgons!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Eradicate! Eradicate!
This is the best show
I've ever seen.
Ah!
Having fun without me again?
[COUGHS]
Jeff, what happened?
You look 70.
Abed has a new
favorite TV show, Jeff.
It's called
Inspector Spacetime.
Can it, boobs!
I came here to let you know
that your best friend Pierce
is the one that got me
kicked out of bio class
and the study group.
It was a plan he hatched
from the beginning
with his pal,
Professor Kane.
But, Jeff, that's a photo
I gave our professor
of me visiting
Hawthorne Wipes'
spokesman and rap artist Sugar
Cube in prison during the '90s.
Well, they--
They look alike.
I guess they share one
important feature in your eyes.
That's not fair!
[STAMMERING]
I-- I was standing far away,
and I saw
the prison uniform!
Oh, Jeffrey!
Oh, come on,
obviously I don't mean all
black people are in prison!
ALL:
Oh!
Jeff, clearly you have
gone off the deep end.
Don't blame him.
The table is powerful,
and being cut off from it--
Shut the...
I've become agitated.
I apologize.
We'll continue this discourse
at a later date.
Good night.
He just needs some space.
Ah!
[ALL SCREAMING]
I'm going to kill
the one thing you love!
I'm gonna kill it!
As long as it breathes,
it controls our lives!
[SIGHS]
I just came by
to tell everyone
this year isn't gonna be
that different.
With the notable exception,
we really won't have any money.
Have a nice night.
What is with that guy?
[SIGHS]
Did you find the monkey?
No, but here's the invoice.
As it turns out,
I can't pay this
or your salaries starting
on two weeks ago.
But, what I do have
are these vouchers
for the classes
of your choosing.
[SIGHS]
You're lucky I need
my scuba certification.
[LOUD POUNDING]
[CHANG EXCLAIMS]
[GRUNTING]
Okay, okay.
I'm the one living
in your vents.
I have no home and no job.
Does that mean you'll work
for room and board?
Okay, I was lying
the whole time.
I didn't want the group
to evolve.
I just didn't want Pierce
around.
I hate him.
But, Jeff, what you did,
it's hard to get past that.
I know you're already
out of the study group,
but I'm gonna have to ask
that you stop being my friend.
Okay, look, everybody,
here's the thing,
I am not as evolved
as I said I was.
The Biology class was full,
so I told Professor Kane
I'd pay him
a few thousand dollars
to kick Jeff out.
What?
ANNIE: Pierce!
BRITTA: What?
Jeff attacked
a table with a fire axe
and only managed to be the
second craziest in the room.
Everybody in favor
of voting Pierce out?
Stop! Stop!
Pierce isn't crazy.
The table
is magic.
As someone who's been
on the other side,
I can tell you,
it is a scary, lonely,
Chang-filled world out there,
and sure, this group
has sprouted some legs,
but why are we in such a rush
to leave the tide pool,
when the only things
waiting for us on shore
are the sands of time
and the seagulls
of slowly growing apart?
Man, I really need
this Biology class.
JEFF:
Pierce.
Professor Kane has never taken
a bribe from anyone in his life.
You feel me?
I lied, but you seem
to have a harder time being
the bad guy than me.
You're right. I do.
Which, in a weird way,
makes me a pretty bad guy.
We're one and the same.
Please don't.
Jeff, but you're still
kicked out of Biology.
Oh, I'm not
worried about it.
Life has a way
of breaking through.
So, uh, here's what
I'm thinking.
I'm a drug dealer, right?
And you're a scientist,
so couldn't we get, like,
a Breaking Bad
type of thing going?
Sorry, Star-Face, you just lost
your seat in my class.
There, now the table
is good as new.
So is Abed.
Britta, I'm sorry I was
overprotective of Abed.
I'll be more supportive.
Here's your first chance.
Helping Abed has inspired me
to finally declare a major.
I'm gonna
study Psychology.
Like in a research capacity?
No, in a hands-on capacity.
I'm gonna be a therapist.
Oh.
Hey, hey, hey,
keep it down.
There's a new sheriff
in town.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Oh, interesting.
So this is the year we all die.
We're all gonna die.
This is our last year.