By the end of World War II,
President Roosevelt's body
finally succumbed
to the polio that afflicted him
his entire life.
Which brings me
to the Yalta Conference.
Who can tell me three key points
brought up there? Annie.
The demilitarization
of Germany--
I'm sorry. Annie Kim.
Demilitarization
of Germany,
establishment
of Poland's borders,
and formation
of the United Nations.
Side note,
the results of Yalta
would later set the stage
for the Cold War.
CLIGORIS:
Oh, boy, spoiler alert.
Somebody just won a ride
in the wheelchair.
I'm proud of you
for deciding on a major.
I'd think the Lord heard
my prayers,
but you still dress like
a streetwalker.
Yep, I'm getting serious.
I got a backpack,
a new notebook.
I got one of
those yellow pens
so I can do that thing
where you color in words.
Highlight?
Probably the backpack.
Free the Damascus Three.
Oh, thanks. Oh. Whoa!
I know this girl.
We used to protest together.
Now she's locked up in Syria.
Oh, that's terrible.
Yes, it's terrible.
She's imprisoned by
an oppressive regime
halfway around the world
and I'm, what, in college?
Where are
my values?
Man, she's got
a Facebook group?
My first cop flashlight.
Can't wait to get
some brains on this bad boy.
Are you safe, ma'am?
Everything okay?
Is this guy
bothering you? Huh?
Who the hell
do you think you are?
Badge says
"To serve and protect."
No, it doesn't.
"How's my smile?"
Oh, man. What the hell
am I in charge of?
See this garbage can?
Students bump into it.
You can serve and protect them
from a boo-boo.
What do I do
if I see a crime?
What a security
guard does.
Call a cop.
Where did you
even get these?
Let me keep them.
No.
I swear they're
just for sex!
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
And this ragtag group of cutups
is my study group.
Gang, this is Annie Kim
from my Poli-Sci class.
We had the same GPA
in high school.
Mine was higher if you consider
my school's ranking.
You had a lighter
course load.
KIM:
I was in a lot of clubs.
I founded 17.
I was thinking about founding
a Model UN at Greendale.
I'll probably be busy.
You probably need to study,
so see you in class.
ANNIE:
Okay, bye.
Wow, Annie,
how progressive of you
to have a multicultural
evil twin.
An Asian Annie.
Obama's America.
Her name is Annie Kim.
And she's not evil,
she's my friend.
Didn't look like it.
You seemed competitive.
Be careful, Annie,
they are ruthless.
What?
Not Asians. Women.
I'm not competing with her.
I find her adorable.
She's like a younger me.
The you that took
so much Adderall
she tried to straighten
the lines
on our football field during
a game?
Careful.
You don't want this girl
to suck you back
to the dark side.
Guys, what are you trying
to do? This is our Annie.
That little twerp
is a can of Annie Lite.
She couldn't hold a candle
to the real thing
in any category of anything.
I wasn't fishing for that.
You're the best, kiddo.
You know what else was the best?
The rain forests.
Too bad the fascist oligarchies
are raping them
to make hamburgers.
Look it up.
Someone woke up
on the regular side of the bed.
Britta's just having
a rough time
because her friend's in prison.
I went to her Facebook page.
It says she was tear-gassed
and possibly beaten.
I haven't been tear-gassed
in so long.
Well, you're on
a new path now.
Oh, goody,
a new path.
Is it lined with credit cards
and flat-screen TVs?
Does it go by an Ikea?
Maybe I don't want a new path.
Or any path.
Maybe my path is a war path
that leads to the Terrordome,
N-words.
Okay, maybe I went too far.
Maybe I don't wanna offend
my African-American friends,
but the larger point is
maybe I'm not done
raging against the machine!
Raging against what?
Sounds dangerous.
Don't worry,
she'll be bad at it.
Keep clear of the can.
Sir, step around
the can.
Mind the can,
student.
[LIONEL RICHIE'S "HELLO"
PLAYING]
♪ Hello ♪
♪ Is it me
You're looking for? ♪
♪ I can see it in your eyes ♪
You got yourself a warning.
I piss warnings, pig.
♪ You're all
I've ever wanted ♪
♪ And my arms are open wide ♪
♪ 'Cause you know
Just what to say ♪
[GAGGING]
And that's
how we do that.
Hey.
I got my eye on you,
missy.
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
Uh!
Oh.
Sorry.
Hi.
You okay, kiddo?
Yeah. You know
what's funny?
Remember little Annie Kim,
from Poli-Sci?
Boy, she just took my Model UN
idea and just...
Pfft! She is quite
the little go-getter.
Wait, what?
She stole your idea?
Sneak attack.
That's just like--
Not women. Asians.
The real important thing
is that there is a Model UN.
It doesn't really matter
who starts it.
It just means her name goes
on some charter
and she gets to put it
on her résumé.
And lead the Greendale team
to the National Model UN.
Meet Kofi Annan,
Boutros Boutros-Ghali
and Will.i.am.
Boutros Boutros-Ghali?
I'm gonna find
this brat's off switch.
Jeff. He's just being
protective, I'll stop him.
I am so excited
that we finally have
a Model UN here at Greendale.
I am really, really, really
into Model UNs.
They used to call me
Model UN Guy back in college.
Well, that's not--
Don't research that.
The important thing here
is that I am really--
Pardon me,
Professor Cligoris.
Cligoris?
Either pronunciation is fine.
Here for the Model UN?
I'm here to tell you
that the entire idea
to have a Model UN was hers.
Really?
So you're Clark M. Eichelberger?
So I've had your photo around
my neck since high school?
I'm talking about
the Greendale Model UN.
My Annie gave this
other Annie the idea
and the diabolical busybody
stabbed her in the back.
It's childish.
Honestly, I'm just happy
there is a Model UN.
Annie, is this true?
I recall other Annie
mentioning the concept,
but she didn't take
the initiative
to find a faculty adviser.
I didn't know you had
to call dibs.
I'm not calling dibs,
because I'm not a child
that steals ideas.
I refuse to acknowledge
the authority
of your criminal Model UN.
So don't recognize it.
It still exists.
Well, then Annie will just start
her own Model UN.
Yeah, for grown-ups.
I still don't recognize it.
It exists, baby.
I don't understand
your relationship.
Is he your father or your lover?
CLIGORIS: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
There can only be one Model UN
that represents this school,
so let's take our foot
off the crazy pedal.
Only one way to settle this.
A head-to-head Model UN
battle royal,
the rules to which I would have
to spend the evening devising.
A competition tomorrow
in the cafeteria at 7 p.m.
May the most united nations win.
Fair enough.
Totally fair.
I'll see you in the fair papers,
other Annie.
Oh, and you were asking
what our relationship is?
We're friends.
Yeah.
Good friends.
Grown-up friends.
JEFF: Just friends.
I'm friendly.
So the key to winning
this thing is,
when in doubt,
agree with Annie.
That's sweet.
Everyone should just have fun.
Then again, what's more
fun than winning?
PIERCE: Absolutely.
Pierce?
I'm offended you'd
single me out.
Did you read your
info packet?
Yes.
Somalia has 1900 miles
of coastline,
a government
that knows its place
and all the guns
and wives you can afford.
Why have I not heard
of this paradise before?
I studied up on my country.
Is it okay if we do accents,
sugar?
Troy, Georgia the country,
not the state.
That's right, capital city,
Tbilisi,
and former member
of the Soviet Union
and we kindly request
y'all mind your P's and Q's.
Welcome to the world's
first-ever Model UN-off.
You will each be scored
on your UN's ability
to pass resolutions,
follow procedure
and maintain order.
The end goal, of course,
total world peace.
Any questions?
Does two UNs mean
there are two Earths?
Uh, yeah, sure. Two Earths.
Parallel Earths
or identical Earths?
The latter.
What about free will?
Abed. Professor.
Yeah, let's begin.
Ready, set, peace.
Crisis alert. A civil war
has broken out in Ethiopia.
Rebel forces have seized
the grain supply,
creating a humanitarian
disaster.
Okay, cool heads, everyone.
America proposes
a UN peacekeeping force
of 10,000 troops.
Uruguay agrees.
Oh, China too.
Georgia, the country,
is much obliged.
Refugees.
Who can take refugees?
The great country of Somalia,
this gem, this Shangri-la,
graciously invites the Ethiopian
refugees to enjoy safe lodging
and cool ocean breezes
on the sand-swept beaches.
Okay, we're rolling.
Switzerland proposes a summit.
Good idea.
Maybe at the summit we can
discuss a portal to Earth Two.
Can we put a pin in that?
Can't ignore it forever.
Ooh! China has money.
Does anybody want some?
Yes, United States proposes
using China's money
to fund agricultural programs
to support Ethiopia's
sustainable farms,
which should promote economic
development and security.
All in favor?
It's unanimous.
CLIGORIS: Good resolving.
You covered all the bases.
We have a unanimous decision.
After one round,
we are tied.
Looks like both UNs are experts
at fostering unity.
Crap.
Damn it.
Crisis alert. Russia...
This is what the United Nations
is doing to your freedom.
I'm your freedom,
and I'm in a cage
with the world,
because of them.
Thought I'd find
you here.
What are you gonna do,
lock me up?
Give me a reason.
I'll give you a reason.
Whoa!
Argh! Aah!
That's it,
you're coming with me.
♪ Hello ♪
♪ Is it me
You're looking for? ♪
He's pulling my cage.
I'm being pulled in my cage
for no reason.
Is anybody seeing this?
Are we Facebooking this?
Crisis alert.
A tsunami has hit Vietnam.
Flooding has left thousands
homeless. Crisis alert!
Tuberculosis outbreak.
Humanitarian aid. We resolve...
Disarmament treaty.
To help women
and children...
To save the orphans.
Loose nukes. Sinkhole.
North Korea.
The prime minister in exile.
Military coup.
The tropical paradise
of Somalia yields.
China will pay.
Gooder than grits.
Switzerland is concerned.
Uruguay agrees.
Uruguay sounds like Ur-a-gay.
Uruguay kindly requests
Somalia stop pronouncing it
Ur-a-gay.
Hereditary monarchy!
Resolved.
Corruption!
Crisis alert!
ANNIE &amp; KIM:
Resolved.
Looking good,
Blue UN.
Getting very close
to world peace.
That's my girl.
You are kicking ass.
All right, guys,
this is the homestretch.
All we gotta do is focus.
Whoo! Damn, Pierce.
Ooh. That wasn't me.
I don't smell anything.
I just got it.
Oh, it's in my mouth.
Guys, come on, focus.
Like adults.
We're gonna lose a point
if we don't get through this.
Get through it?
It's almost a solid.
Crisis alert!
A genocidal dictator in Laos--
Yeah, yeah,
we'll get to that. Ooh!
Okay, so, Turkey,
what can you do?
So let me get this straight.
You're bringing her in here
for making a mess?
I did more than
make a mess.
I turned your whole
system inside out.
I shut her down.
You spilled paint
on a globe.
You're as much a criminal
as this idiot is a cop.
None whatsoever.
Okay, but she's going to do
something illegal, aren't you?
NUNEZ:
Is that true?
Do you, Britta Perry,
have any intentions
of breaking any laws, ever?
Uh...
Oh, my God.
No, it's not that simple.
I have a life now.
I have a major and--
Get out, please.
I have highlighters.
Get out!
[BRITTA SOBBING]
Okay, I know you got a lot
on your mind right now,
but somebody broke the thing
that comes down
from the parking booth.
The thing that comes down,
keeps the cars from coming in.
The thing. It's like a gate,
but it's just a stick.
It comes down,
on a hinge.
Keeps the cars out.
It goes up and down 90 degrees.
The arm?
[SMACKS LIPS]
CLIGORIS:
Another point goes
to the red team.
[TROY &amp; ABED CHUCKLING]
How is this
still happening?
I can't remember
what regular air smells like.
Do something.
We're gonna lose.
Guys, this is
important to Annie.
So whoever actually died
a few months ago, 'fess up
so we can put a stake
through your heart.
ALL: Ha, ha, ha.
Jeff!
I think the lesson here
is that a Model UN,
like the real UN,
falls apart when faced
with actual--
No!
I think the lesson here
is that I need to win this!
I wanna win!
And you, you suck!
You're a stupid, ugly poop-face
and I'm better than you!
Annie, stop.
You're acting like
a little schoolgirl,
and not in a hot way.
[ALL GASP]
[CROWD MURMURING]
Okay, that made me sound creepy.
But here's the thing...
[♪♪♪]
Don't look at me.
If embarrassment were
bountiful zinc deposits,
I'd be Zambia.
There's nothing to be
Zambia about, Annie.
This is all my fault.
I pushed you into competing
with other Annie.
Are you kidding me?
I practically ran to you
with that flyer.
I wanted to destroy her,
all because I can't handle
the thought of anyone getting
more gold stars than me.
I'm such a child.
You're not.
When you really hate someone
the way you hate Annie Kim,
or when you feel the way
I feel about you,
the easy loophole through
the creepiness and danger
is to treat them
like a child.
"Chip off the old block.
You're the best, kiddo."
It's a crutch.
It's a way for me to tell you
how important you are,
from a distance.
But now you're becoming
this mature, intelligent
young woman
and I can't keep patting you
on the head
or talking down
to you.
But I like
how close we are.
I don't wanna grow up
if it means losing what we have.
Well, tough, Annie.
You have to grow up
because the world needs
more women like you.
We can't keep doing
this forever, kiddo.
Can't we?
Nope, I can't. No. No.
No, that's gross. I feel gross.
I'd better go check
on the group,
if they haven't left.
I'll follow you.
From a respectable distance.
[INDISTINCT DIALOGUE]
Guys, I'm sorry
I put you through that.
And I know it doesn't make up
for what happened,
but would it help
if I said I farted?
Annie, no. I can't let you
fall on that sword
because I farted.
No. I farted.
I farted.
I wasn't doing
the Spartacus thing.
I farted.
No, seriously--
We all farted.
Oh, you guys.
I'm farting now.
Wait, why are you still here?
Abed may have figured out
a way we can still win.
Really? How?
It's simple. First we...
[WHISPERING]
And then I go...
You circle around...
Abed, what did I tell you?
You can't just mumble nonsense.
No one's cutting away.
Here's my actual plan.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
Aah! Aah!
What is that?
It's from Britta.
She's promising to disrupt
the Model UN.
She says she's gonna
cause a disruption
that, while not
completely illegal,
should be of real concern
to campus security.
I don't know. Maybe we should
call the real cops.
Back in the '80s,
I had this real piece-of-work
protestor
who used to always
give me trouble.
You know what happened
to her?
She incited a riot at the WTO.
Got choked till she passed out.
By some real cop
with a real billy club.
Sometimes I wonder,
you know.
Well, what are
you waiting for?
Go show that hippie
how the world really works.
Are you forgetting something?
All in favor?
Aye.
Could you morons say "aye"
any slower? Come on.
[RATTLING]
[BUZZING NOISE]
CROWD:
Whoa!
[CROWD MURMURING]
[GROUP MAKING
BUZZING NOISE]
[MAKES CLICKING NOISE]
Greetings, people of Earth Two.
What is this?
We represent the United Nations
from Earth One.
Using our Switzerland's
Hadron Collider
and resources from every nation,
the people of our planet
have constructed
a trans-dimensional
gateway here.
They can't do this.
The science works out.
Yeah.
We come to you with an offer.
We have achieved world peace,
tying our score with yours.
But we are willing to concede
our victory
if you agree conceding yours,
forming one, gigantic,
united United Nations.
We did it.
KIM: You're a fool.
Your ultimatum is itself
a technical act of aggression.
If we simply refuse
to recognize your authority,
we still remain ahead
and you lose.
But you win a simple game.
The larger, symbolic victory
will be ours.
Ooh-la-la.
We refuse.
I'll take the real victory.
A logical, effective,
common-sense move, Annie Kim,
one which flies in the very face
of the United Nations itself,
a fundamentally symbolic
organization
founded on the principles
of high-minded rhetoric
and empty gestures.
Blue UN wins.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
[BRITTA SCREAMING]
What the hell are you doing?
Nothing.
And you can't do anything
to stop me.
CHANG:
Did someone say,
"Can't do anything"?
[LIONEL RICHIE'S "HELLO"
PLAYING]
♪ Hello ♪
♪ Is it me
You're looking for? ♪
♪ I can see it in your eyes ♪
♪ I can see it in your smile ♪
♪ You're all I've ever wanted ♪
[ALL GASP]
♪ And my arms are open wide ♪
♪ 'Cause you know
Just what to say ♪
♪ And you know
Just what to do ♪
So that's nice.
No?
♪ And I want to tell you
So much ♪
I knew you'd come.
You're so busted.
♪ I love you ♪
Yes.
[SNORTS]
TROY:
Shit.
I told you to stop playing
Operation on me!
I'm not your damn board game!
At least you didn't
get my spare ribs.