[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Remember, you guys
can have dip, too.
And don't be afraid
to play with the
[SPOOKILY]
rubber spider!
I'll ask again,
are you sure
I can't bring anything?
I don't understand.
We're having a party,
before we're going
to the real party?
I think you young people
are just making this crap up.
It's a pre-party!
It's informal, intimate,
and just for us.
And I told you guys
you didn't have to dress up.
Oh, we were wearing
this when you called.
Yeah, when we dress up,
you'll know it.
There's nothing in your playlist
but Spooky Party,
the Beetlejuice soundtrack,
and NPR podcasts.
Ooh! We could listen
to one of those!
I have Michele Norris
interviewing Errol Morris.
Don't worry,
they address it.
Okay,
let's make this quick.
I got three more polite
appearances to make tonight.
[LAUGHS]
What? I'm one of
the Fast &amp; Furious guys.
Which one?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't watch that shallow crap.
I just pick a costume
girls will like.
Jeff, can I have a quick
conversation with you?
Doubtful,
but I support the dream.
Remember last week,
when I made you guys fill out
those anonymous personality
tests for my psych class?
Listen, if you dropped them
in another puddle...
No, I processed the results
as per my assignment.
And, Jeff,
one of our friends is
deeply disturbed.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
Trick or dean!
[GASPS]
Don't forget to come by our
Halloween Scare-tacular dance
starting in the
cafeteria at 9:30.
Also, I had the lights
rigged to flicker
because it's Halloween!
It's been happening
for a week.
Halloween week!
So the lights will work
on November 1st?
All Saints' Day...Month!
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
I'm sorry, you were
about to get ridiculous?
Look!
One of the tests came back
with 70 out of 75 red flags
for an extreme
personality disorder.
Extreme, Jeff!
Ah! Like a Dorito?
A sociopathic Dorito.
A Cool Ranch lunatic.
Only instead of zest,
Jeff,
one member
of our study group has
homicidal tendencies.
♪ It's a spooky party ♪
I think one member
of our study group
is an overzealous
psych major.
You probably just Britta'd
the test results somehow.
No. I double-checked them.
Wait.
Are people using my name
to mean
"make a small mistake"?
Yes.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Let's make this party
fast and furious,
in that order.
Yeah, I want to go
to the dance.
I heard the dean's got
free taco meat from the army.
We can go
to the dance in a bit.
But first, why don't we
tell some scary stories?
[ALL GROANING]
Good!
I'll start with a story
about a horrible fate
befalling innocent people,
and then I'm curious
to get individual reactions.
Once upon a time,
there was a couple
in a car in the woods
making out or something.
I think I heard something.
It's just the sound
of my heart, baby.
Mmm.
MAN [ON RADIO]:
In the news tonight,
top story.
An escaped convict
from the asylum has escaped,
and he's mental and
he's on the loose and stuff.
Oh, my God.
That sounds dangerous.
Oh, I'm sure
it's no biggie,
but I am a horny man.
I'm only half-present.
He was last seen in the woods
and has a thingy for a hand,
a hook thing
where his hand should be.
You know what I mean.
That sounds dangerous.
Fine,
I'll get out and look.
But then
I'm entitled to sex.
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
I'm getting stabbed
with his hook hand thing.
Oh, my God! No!
I was right!
The woman was
screaming and screaming
and the man got killed.
Abed?
Yep?
How did that story
make you feel?
Embarrassed.
That's an odd reaction.
[ALL DISAGREEING]
TROY: Seems fair.
What embarrassed you
about it?
I didn't care
about the characters.
Didn't care about them?
They put themselves in danger.
They were warned about it,
the guy got out of the car.
Do you believe because he was
stupid he deserved to die?
What the hell
kind of party is this?
From a creative standpoint,
some characters deserve to die.
Ones that lack common sense
or basic survival instinct.
It's not scary because the
characters are making choices
the audience wouldn't make.
You need a smarter lead.
Here, like this.
It's a dark,
cold night in the woods.
We establish a traditional log
cabin, then cut to...
Here we are,
a log cabin I rented so we could
be intimate in safety,
because it's not the '50s,
so we don't have to neck
at Inspiration Point.
That makes sense. I'm turned on
by how logical you are.
I'm comforted by your shiny hair
and facial symmetry.
Well,
I just brushed my teeth,
so this would be
the optimal time to kiss.
Enjoyable. Soft lips.
Just the right
level of moisture.
Would you like to do it again?
No.
We should listen
to the news on this radio.
I brought it
as a cautionary measure,
because this cabin
is within walking distance
of the local insane asylum.
Oh, is that why
you were able to rent this
at such a reasonable rate?
Yes.
I hope you're as fertile
as I am tonight.
More.
[SMOOTH JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
BRITTA:
Ah.
[HUMMING JAZZ MELODY]
Abed! Why are you doing
the whole song?
They wouldn't turn the radio on
at the exact moment
of the most pertinent
news broadcast.
But I'll jump forward in time.
[CLATTERS]
What was that noise?
Based on the news report
we just heard,
I assume it's the hook-handed
killer, who escaped
when the asylum's antiquated
security system failed.
I guess they
shouldn't have cut corners,
although it is understandable,
given the economic downturn.
Should we go check it out?
No. We should call 911
on my fully-charged cell phone,
lock the doors,
and then stand back to back
in the middle
of the room holding knives.
[♪♪♪]
I love you...
Shh!
[♪♪♪]
Ugh! Did these people
ever die or what?
Eventually,
once it had been...
[SPOOKILY]
...earned!
JEFF:
Well, Britta,
it looks like you're
barking up the wrong tree.
Yeah. You want to
hear a scary story?
I've got a scary story.
[♪♪♪]
Thank you for pulling me
from that carriage.
I don't know what could have
frightened my horses so.
Many vile creatures
make these woods their home.
Some even warn
of...monsters.
I don't believe
in monsters.
I believe every man
has good within.
I must retrieve my books
from the debris tomorrow.
I am a schoolteacher,
and many children rely
on me to educate them.
Be gone,
innocent one!
What's wrong?
You may choose
not to believe in them,
but I am a monster.
And I must feed.
Do not judge me
for my weakness.
Stifle your slackened maw,
you drained
and tainted bitch dog.
[GASPS]
I'm fine with this.
Ah!
Wait!
Teach me to read.
Aw.
Wo...
Sound it out.
Word... Dog...
Mmm-hmm.
...hates cats.
"O reason not the need!
"Our basest beggars are in the
poorest things superfluous."
Yes! Yes! Yes!
You should be proud
of how much I've changed you.
Thank you
for helping me,
but I'm afraid
some monsters
cannot change.
No...
Resist your craving!
Just pick up a good book
and read!
Your porcelain neck,
in the light
of the full moon...
Too appetizing.
Unfortunate...
For you.
You see,
some monsters cannot change.
But others can.
What is this?
I'm a werewolf that feeds
on selfish vampires.
[GROWLING]
[HISSES]
And she ripped
into his torso,
like a gerbil shredding
a Quaker Oats box,
sending chunks of viscera
and an aerosol mist of blood
all over the skanky concubine.
Then, she flossed her teeth
with his tendons.
And, because
he was a vampire,
he lived through all of it.
He had to watch her
swallow his last eyeball.
She kept it attached
to the optic nerve,
so he could see
down her throat,
to his own
partially digested flesh
in her stomach.
Hmm?
Mmm!
[SIGHS]
See? There was a twist.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
Wow, Annie.
I didn't know you were
such a fan of...gore.
It's Halloween. If you're
gonna tell a scary story,
give it some texture.
Wasn't that great.
Well, your texture was so
discompassionately macabre,
as if without the slightest
regard for human life.
That's enough.
Stop pinning ribbons to her.
Why does Annie get to be
good at everything?
You guys wanna hear a real,
legit scary story?
[♪♪♪]
Hello?
Is there anyone here?
I need help.
Oh, thank God.
An old doctor.
Me and my partner
are top gun fighter pilots,
the best of the best.
[IMITATES GUN FIRING]
Our F-15 went down
in the woods.
I thought I heard
something awesome out there.
Please, come in,
for first aids
and what have you.
Mmm, drinks from a stranger.
So medical.
Thank you.
Ah.
Wakey-wakey.
What's going on?
This cabin is my lab,
where I do weird
experiments on people.
Look!
BOTH:
No!
Forced to be together forever!
I sewed you together.
I totally
sewed you together!
[LAUGHS]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
TROY:
Abed!
Now that we're sewn together,
do we have ESP?
ABED:
Yes! We're psychic now.
We can destroy him
with mind powers.
Ow!
[♪♪♪]
You tried
to destroy us...
But you only made us...
BOTH:
More awesome!
No! I'm legit jealous.
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
Now you
are the subject.
What? What?
Tell me more.
We sewed your butt
to your chest! Ha!
No!
Wait.
Ha! You fools!
By sewing my butt
to my chest,
you've given me boobs
I can touch all day.
BOTH:
With what?
No!
[GROANING]
Feet hands.
What did I do
to deserve that?
Keep me out of
your stupid stories.
I didn't say it was you.
I said he was a crazy, old,
racist doctor.
Yeah, and I'm your crazy, old,
racist friend.
I was, anyway.
Now I'm not so sure.
It's just a story, Pierce.
Yeah?
Well, so is this.
[FUNKY MUSIC PLAYING]
Come back to bed,
Magnum.
In a moment, girls.
I'm just enjoying an expensive,
post-coital brandy.
[ALL WHINE]
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
Whats we gots heres?
This is a home invasion,
you jive mother.
Easy, easy, easy.
Nobody has
to get hurt here.
Yeah, that's right, honky.
You take it real easy
and give us all your
expensive brandy and hubcaps.
[LAUGHS]
Okay, but...
BOTH:
Whoa!
Oh, man.
You are still relevant!
[FLY UNZIPS]
Oh, my God!
[FLY ZIPS UP]
Okay, I'm ready
for my birthday spanking.
Which of you girls
knows how to count to 30?
What in the hell
was that?
TROY:
That wasn't
even a ghost story.
It was like an episode
of some show
we're all too young
to have heard of.
Fine! Then I chopped up
both your bodies.
So that was us
and you were Magnum?
Still am, Pakistan.
Wanna try me?
Guys, I think these stories
are starting to get personal.
And so needlessly violent.
What happened to the days
when ghost stories
were about good versus evil?
Once upon a time...
[HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Aw, man.
My drugs are wearing off.
Who's got more?
[LAUGHS]
Here you go, baby.
JEFF:
All right, all right.
That is my kind
of pot bong.
[LOUD GROWLING OUTSIDE]
Yo, Jango,
check it out.
Swarms of locusts
and tornadoes of frogs.
I don't care.
I lived in New York.
[BRITTA SCREAMS]
[ALL SCREAMING]
Ugh! It's like
New York out there.
MAN [ON RADIO]:
We interrupt your metal
to bring you some news.
All the good Christians
got raptured up to heaven,
so if you're hearing this,
the good news is you're the
coolest people in the world.
ALL:
Yes!
The bad news is the world
is over. This is NPR.
Aw, man.
End of days?
Could anything suck
harder than this?
Hell-o!
Devil here.
Just popping by with a little
damnation orientation.
Here's the sched.
At 10, you'll be buried
neck-deep in scorpions.
11:15, lava enemas,
followed by Pilates.
Oh. That's good.
I like Pilates.
Pilates is a demon
that eats your genitals.
[ALL EXCLAIM]
But first,
stabby-stabby.
Ha-ha-ha!
[ALL SCREAMING]
For whom do ye cry out?
All the good people are gone!
[DEMON CACKLING]
[SCREAMS]
Whoa! Look!
It's our friend we used to
pick on for being Christian.
ANNIE:
Oh, she looks great.
Aah!
A righteous wind blows!
Off to Pilates!
Thank you for
saving us, Shirley.
I mean,
your name's not Shirley,
this is a story
about strangers.
Anyhoo, can you take us
to heaven now, please?
Ooh, I cannot.
I just came to say goodbye
on my way to Abraham's bosom.
Bye.
I forgive you.
[CHAINSAW REVVING]
Gay marriage!
And he chainsaw-ed
them to bits!
Then he put 'em
back together.
And then he chainsaw-ed
them again! Forever.
Where was Jeff
in that story?
And why was
my name Jango?
Shirley, that wasn't
a horror story.
That was a sermon.
You ruined a Britta party.
That's like
letting poop spoil.
No! Wait! No!
No one can leave
until we figure this out.
Figure what out?
BRITTA: Long story short,
those psych tests
I made you take came back.
Turns out one of you is
probably a homicidal maniac.
That's stupid.
I have a responsibility,
as a practitioner
of the mental arts,
to figure out which
one of you is sick,
and get you
the treatment you need.
You're a danger to yourself
and others.
We've known each other
for two years.
None of us are murderers.
No, but one of you
has the potential.
If we leave here now,
do you know what might happen?
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[BOTH GROAN]
[♪♪♪]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[BOTH GROANING]
[CHOKING]
Britta, what are
you describing?
What?
Who has images like that
in their head?
The same kind of person
that would make us
tell ghost stories in order
to study our minds.
I'm just worried
that one of you...
One of us? You took
that test too, right?
What?
What are you saying?
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHS]
[GASPS]
Oh, my God!
What if it is me?
[ALL CHATTERING]
Wait. This is crazy!
We're getting freaked out
because it's Halloween.
We just need
to settle down.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[ALL SHOUTING]
I'll kill you!
You don't want
to be barium-sulfated!
Get away from me!
Stay back, psychos!
Or I'll slit your throats
and bathe in your blood.
Whoa! What has happened
to all of you?
You heard
all the stories.
Anyone here could
be a psycho!
Thinking that
is what's psycho.
Here, I have a story
that I think might help.
Whee!
Cheers.
[ALL SCREAMING]
Whoa, whoa. Wait!
Before you do anything,
tell us why
you kill people.
Fear.
I kill because
I'm afraid.
Somebody, please,
give me a hug.
ALL:
Aw!
Get in here.
Love hugs. Love hugs.
Let it out.
It's okay.
You're welcome.
That was the gayest crap
I've heard in my life.
Yeah, Jeff.
What the hell?
Why are you always so determined
to have us put down our weapons?
Maybe he's a remorseless madman
with no empathy,
who eludes detection
by manipulating others.
ANNIE:
Yeah, Jeff.
Maybe we should go through
your test answers one by one.
It doesn't matter.
I filled mine out randomly.
TROY: Oh, come on.
BRITTA: What?
You idiot!
That was probably the test that
returned the psychotic result!
Hmm. Maybe.
ANNIE: What kind of sociopath
doesn't offer that information
an hour ago?
No, no.
I'm no sociopath.
I always know
what I'm doing is wrong.
I'm just a guy that doesn't like
taking tests, doing work,
or getting yelled at.
So if you think about it,
that makes me
the sanest person here.
[ALL BOOING]
Is this your test
or what?
How should I know?
It's just a bunch of bubbles.
Wait! Give me those.
Why are the scores on the
bottoms of the sheets?
They should...
Britta, look at the arrow.
You ran these through
the machine upside-down.
She Britta'd it.
Whatever. I'll run them
through again.
And you guys are gonna stop
using my name
to mean "making a tiny
and understandable mistake."
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[♪♪♪]
So we're all insane.
Well, except
for this person.
Is that one mine?
We should probably
figure it out, right?
If one of us
isn't crazy,
it's only fair that
the rest of us know.
Or we could hold on
to the comforting notion
that any one of us
might be sane.
Yeah. Okay.
We learned an
important lesson tonight.
We should never
make the Britta
of Britta-ing
each other's feelings.
You're using it wrong.
Wow.
You Britta'd "Britta'd."
Yeah, way to pull an Abed.
I don't get it.
JEFF:
Shirley, don't Pierce.
I don't get it.
[♪♪♪]
Guys,
it's been three days!
When are you
gonna let me go?
At least say something!
Guys? Guys!
ABED:
Should we let him go?
TROY:
Hmm, let me think.
Nah. More brandy?
ABED:
Don't mind if I do.
Mmm, that's terrible.
Should we get back in our F-15
that we repaired
with our mind power?
I was thinking
the same thing!
BOTH:
I know! Jinx!
Double jinx!
Triple jinx! Ha-ha!
BOTH:
♪ Troy and Abed
Sewn together ♪
[THUNDER CRASHES]