[♪♪♪]
Damn it!
Put the teethy wrench on the
square thing and jiggle it left.
[DISHWASHER WHIRRING]
Thanks. By the way,
that square thing
is a Hampton bolt
and a Manacheck maneuver.
Hey. Hey, I'm just here
for the Tater Tots.
Wait.
Look, I know you think
you made your mind up about
plumbing, and I respect that.
But come to the third floor
men's room tomorrow after 3.
Unclog one toilet and tell me
you don't feel something,
and I'll never
bring it up again.
All right. One toilet.
If it will get you
off my back.
Abed, look.
Cool. Stonehenge.
MAN:
Have him sign it.
Excuse me.
Are you Pierce Hawthorne
of Hawthorne Wipes?
At your cervix.
Sorry,
I thought you were a lady.
You can use that cervix line
if you want.
I told you it was him.
Mind signing this?
He's a big fan.
♪ I got a pocket full
Of Hawthornes ♪
♪ Pocket full of Hawthornes ♪♪
Okay, Randall, power down.
What was that about?
Fans of the product.
In the wipes business,
we call them towel-heads.
You got through a conversation
with two gay men
without doing this--
Wait. Those guys were--
I assumed they were just
brothers or wealthy.
Why did they wanted
your autograph?
This might be why.
♪ It's Friday night ♪
♪ I'm putting on my highest
Heels, my shortest skirt ♪
♪ My best device
For concealing my penis ♪
♪ And I got everything I need
Ow ♪
♪ I got my body, got my lips ♪
♪ Got a pocket full of
Hawthornes ♪
♪ Pocket full of Hawthornes ♪
Oh, my God, Pierce, your moist
towelettes are a gay icon.
What do Hawthorne Wipes have
to do with the choice to be gay?
Well, according to Wikipedia--
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
Oh! Oh, my.
Even Bruce Vilanch?
Especially Bruce Vilanch.
That is copyright infringement
and defamation.
I'm gonna sue
the pants off that lady.
I don't think that's a lady.
Why do you want his pants off?
Shut up. Only when
I thought he was a lady.
You're attracted to him.
Only thing I'm attracted to
is taking him to court
and eating his ass alive.
Ooh...
That's not what I meant.
Stop putting gay things
in my mouth.
[GROUP LAUGHING]
ABED:
♪ I got a pocket full of
Hawthornes ♪
♪ Pocket full of Hawthornes ♪
It's catchy.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
I hope Pierce doesn't really sue
that lady-man singer.
His life must be hard having
to sew pouches in his skirts.
Yes, I'm always nice
to the gays.
They defy God,
but I'd die
before I let
a woman touch my hair.
Gay-oh! Hey, what's
going on with you bitches?
"Bitches" is gay talk
for "friends."
Did you sue Urbana Champaign
for his T-shirt?
Not at all, I bought this.
I'm a fan.
Also, I'm a gay-rights advocate.
Pierce's positrons have been
negatized, creating Anti-Pierce.
Happens on Inspector Spacetime.
Yeah, but Anti-Inspector
had a funny mustache
and was kind of rape-y.
Don't think his positrons
have been negatized.
Exactly what
Constable Reggie said.
No, I thought about it,
and I decided
a man should not be judged by
what he does with a man's butt.
Here's the kick.
Since that song came out,
Hawthorne Wipes sales
went up 7 percent.
And it's good.
PIERCE: Yep.
Had my own people mock up a
design for a new product line.
Hawthorne Pride Wipes.
They may cost more,
but they're gayer.
I'm gonna launch
these little babies
at a big party here
at Greendale.
Here's a flyer.
Ooh.
"Greendale's
first annual gay bash."
Pierce, congratulations on
meeting the minimum requirements
for open-mindedness.
Yeah, I'm really proud of you.
You're growing as a person.
He's not supporting gay people,
they're supporting him.
If Mexicans were buying,
he'd have ridden in on a donkey.
People earning respect with
money is the American way.
Not that my father
would've agreed.
It took a federal injunction to
get him to sell to the Italians.
I see what's going on.
In my psych class,
I'm learning about
the Edible Complex.
Men have to kill their fathers,
so they can do something
to their mothers.
I haven't finished the chapter.
What's that complex where
you're wrong about everything?
Ha. Sarcasm from the man with
the mother of all daddy issues.
Whoa, double diagnosis.
Save some for all
those poor real doctors.
What type of cookies
do you want?
We have peanut butter
or chocolate chip.
Rainbow, bitches.
We can have peanut butter
or chocolate chip.
[♪♪♪]
Well?
It's pretty great.
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[MAN WHISTLES]
Tight seal, good flow.
Kid's pretty handy.
You get the hell
out of here!
Go on!
[CHUCKLES]
[♪♪♪]
Who was that?
You listen to me.
What you have is a gift.
And some people are gonna try
to take advantage of that gift.
Promise you'll use it for good.
I promise.
Good. Now, come with me
to the second floor.
Somebody pooped in the sink.
[♪♪♪]
We actually
have a lot in common.
We hate lesbians,
we hate baggy pants...
I can't believe you guys
are all Bears fans.
Super fans.
Randall.
Somebody take a picture.
Come on, photo of this.
Okay, let's take
a silly one.
Okay, okay.
All right.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
MAN [IN SOUTHERN ACCENT]:
Piercinald Anastasia Hawthorne.
[♪♪♪]
Father.
We need to talk, boy.
[♪♪♪]
[RATTLING]
Um--
[GASPING]
LAYBOURNE:
Gentlemen.
You are here because you
have been selected as candidates
for the Greendale Air
Conditioning Repair School.
But why kidnap you?
Why put a sack over your head
and drag you here
in the middle of the night?
Why is there an astronaut
in the corner making paninis?
Simple, we don't want you
to tell anyone about this.
And if you do, we don't want
them believing you.
Isn't that right,
Black Hitler?
Your initiation
begins
now, gentlemen.
Hey, guys,
I'm looking for Troy.
He said he's fine,
but couldn't say where he is.
Do you think
he's been kidnapped?
Usually one of the parents,
and almost always ends
in murder-suicide.
Why are you smiling?
I'm smiling?
If you see him, tell him
Jerry's looking for him.
Jeff, what're you gonna wear
to Pierce's party?
Nothing.
Ooh. They'll love that.
Ha, ha. I mean,
I'm not going,
and I can't believe
you're supporting it.
Everybody, this is my father,
Cornelius Hawthorne.
Oh. I always assumed
your father was dead.
Just mathematically.
Mom liked to pretend
that was the case.
These your friends, Pierce?
Hello.
Minorities, Jewesses,
and the unseasonably tan?
That is inappropriate.
And maybe you'll give that
more weight since I'm white.
You've got a wide brow.
What are you, Scandinavian?
Yeah, Swedish.
Swedish dogs.
Your blood is tainted
by generations of race-mixing
with Laplanders.
You're basically Finns.
Goodness,
he's like the Abed of racism.
Since no one's asking,
what's going on with your hair?
Ordinary toupee hair
is harvested
from heads of
the godless Oriental.
Solid ivory
is the only way
to be assured
of true follicular purity
while identifying myself
as a man of means.
I can excuse racism, but I draw
the line at animal cruelty.
You excuse racism?
JEFF: What brings you here?
It's not for your son's party.
Unless "segregationist mummy"
is a gay fetish.
Actually, after discussing
with my father, the party's off,
and we're canceling
Pride Wipes.
Stand up straight when talking
to the lower classes.
Now, excuse me, I need to go
find a half-decent ivory buffer
in this two-horse town.
Oh, the party's canceled?
I bought a cone bra.
Piercinald, please tell me
you did not cancel
because of your father.
It's a business decision, Jeff.
I took a look at the numbers,
had someone explain them,
and this is the way we're going.
You said Pierce's idea was dumb.
Before it was oppressed by--
A father?
A homophobe.
This isn't about fathers.
This is about
a long-suffering community
with constitutional right
to wipe whoever
and whatever they want.
If you like gay people so much,
why don't you marry them?
This is so Edible.
Britta, you'll make
a terrible therapist.
If you need to talk to someone,
I don't recommend you.
That how your dad
talked to your mom?
That's how
he talked to yours.
How does that make you feel?
Shut up.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
Jeffrey!
Ah. I was sad when Pierce said
he was canceling the party.
I was so happy when
you said it was back on.
Yeah, he's busy with his dad,
but I knew how much
it meant to him.
I throw a pretty gay party, huh?
Yeah, it's great, if you're
into that kind of thing.
Time to mingle.
What the hell is this?
Gay bash,
courtesy of Hawthorne Wipes.
I canceled this.
And I uncanceled it.
My dad's gonna disown me.
Oh, no, you'll be
free of him forever.
You'll never have
to cower at his voice,
or shudder when
you see an elephant.
You're welcome, Pierce.
I did what you never
had the guts to do.
Britta was right.
You resent my father
because you've got
problems with your own.
Everything you said
just sounded like a fog horn.
Then have your big gay party.
I'm out of here.
Pierce, have one drink.
You're gonna wanna see
the guest of honor.
Pull the cord, fellas.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Pierce, Pierce, Pierce!
[MAN WHOOPING]
Well, maybe just one drink.
Done.
LAYBOURNE:
Mr. Barnes,
walk with me.
air-conditioning repair
is an elite worldwide family
dating back to the very
beginnings of civilizations.
Our predecessors were slaves,
fanning the pharaohs
with palm fronds.
Over time, we became expert
at making our superiors
comfortable.
We made it our business,
and along the way,
we learned
to make ourselves comfortable.
No more palm fronds, Troy.
Now we are the pharaohs.
[EXHALES]
COMPUTER:
Breath print approved.
Feel that?
Actually, I don't feel--
Precisely.
Have you heard the expression
"room temperature"?
Of course.
This is the room.
This is the room temperature
room.
[♪♪♪]
I can't tell where the air ends
and my skin begins.
It's incredible.
That's what we do, Troy.
Incredible, invisible,
inbelievable things.
We're an unseen, unknown,
unvincible fraternity
of craftsmen.
Graduates of this school are
guaranteed lucrative employment
for their entire lives.
And I'm inviting you to join us.
Will there always be paninis?
There is one catch, Troy.
Once you're in,
you're in.
Air-conditioning repair
will be your life.
A life of secrets you'll be
unable to share with outsiders.
You will be an
air-conditioning repairman
and nothing else
until the day you die.
I don't expect you
to make a decision now.
Take 24 hours.
COMPUTER: Breath print approved.
Cool.
I can't feel my pants.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Go, Pierce. Go, Pierce.
It's your birthday.
Congratulations. You got Pierce
to symbolically kill his father
by dancing to club music.
You should be happy about this.
Pierce is becoming
more tolerant,
and it has nothing to do
with his father.
Look at me now, Dad.
Yeah, look at me now, Dad.
CROWD:
Look at me now, Dad.
Where you been?
Not allowed to say.
Are you Superman?
No.
Would you tell me if you were?
I never understood
why he cared who knew.
This is the hottest party
we've ever had.
It's pretty dope.
No, I mean,
it's dangerously hot.
Our air-conditioning system
wasn't built
for this gay a party.
I'll take a look.
Tron?
What's Tron?
Ooh!
Man, this party's
a real sausage fest.
JERRY: I knew it.
Knew what?
Don't play dumb with me.
Did they promise you
the life of your dreams?
You can have all that
as a plumber too.
Why do you hate them so much?
They're elitist.
They make everybody think
that they're special.
Because the truth is
they're not.
I have a gift. I'm special.
I'm not a loser like you.
I'm gonna eat spaceman paninis
with Black Hitler
and there's nothing
you can do about it!
Wow, you seem
to be enjoying yourself.
I've gotta say, I don't know why
the word "gay" means "dumb."
These guys are all right.
Pierce Hawthorne, get your fine,
gay-loving ass up here
and say something to your fans.
Come on!
[CHEERING]
If I tell you something,
will you keep it a secret?
Secret handshake.
BOTH: Secret.
I said I can't talk to you
about what's going on,
but I can talk to myself.
Can you pretend to be me?
[IMITATING TROY]
I like football,
but also I don't.
I can't choose between
air conditioning and plumbing.
I know, it's so hard, right?
Let's ask Abed.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Now you be me.
[IMITATING TROY]
What should I do?
I don't know,
but Harrison Ford might.
Don't get cocky, kid.
This isn't working.
Abed, tell me what to do.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Plumbing and air conditioning
seem identical.
They're not. They couldn't be
more or less identical.
Well, what do you
feel like doing?
Honestly, I feel like
watching TV with you.
They're making me choose.
If I choose wrong,
it could screw up my life.
If you have to, go with whatever
makes you the happiest.
They're virtually
the same thing.
I think I know
what I need to do.
Don't get cocky, kid.
All right, bitches!
[ALL CHEERING]
I just wanna say
this whole thing...
[♪♪♪]
...was a huge mistake.
Uh, Hawthorne Wipes
is officially
severing its ties
to the gay community.
WOMAN: What?
PIERCE: Effective immediately,
it will return to being
a straights-only product.
[BOOING]
[GRUNTING]
[PEOPLE GASPING]
Fake heart attack.
I taught him
everything he knows.
So how long you guys been
on the force?
Pierce, what the hell was that?
That--
That was my boy.
Standing up for good old
Hawthorne values.
All due respect, sir,
zero respect for you.
Typical Welsh nonsense.
But, Father, I--
Wanna be like this guy?
He's wearing elephant bones.
He will be what I tell him to be
because I am his father.
Listen up, Colonel Cryptkeeper.
I could live a million years
and spend every minute
doing important things.
At the end of it, I would've
only lived half a life
if I had not raised a son.
This was a gift handed to you.
You squandered it.
You have hatred in your heart
is because you're
trying to fill a hole
where your kid was supposed
to go. Now it's too late.
Now you're just stomping around
trying to prove you exist.
Well, mission accomplished.
But here's a question
I'd like to pass on to you
from every son of every
crap dad that ever lived.
So what?
I'm done with you.
He's done with you.
The world is done with you.
[GRUNTING]
Come on in. He's a Hawthorne.
This is what they do.
He's faking.
[BELL TOLLING]
[ORGAN PLAYING]
Pierce, listen,
I just wanna say--
Did you know
that the Canadian mallard
is the only fowl that bites
his father's head off?
That is definitely not true.
I don't know.
I looked it up
on the Wikipedia.
Pierce, um,
I just wanna say, you know,
sorry for killing your dad.
Don't blame yourself.
He bought a lot of his organs
from questionable sources.
Oh, here,
he wanted you to have this.
No, Pierce,
you should take it.
I'd love it.
But terms of his will
state that whoever
kills him gets to keep it.
I guess I'm up.
"Father, I'll never forget
what you said to me
"on my first day of school:
"'Comb your hair, you idiot.
You look Greek.'
"I'll never know
if that's true,
"but I do know that I was too
scared to stand up for myself.
"Well, I'm not scared of you
anymore because you're dead,
"and I'm not.
So I win."
And you can suck it.
Dude just told his dead dad
to suck it.
So Edible.
You're the worst.
[AIR BLOWING]
[♪♪♪]
[AIR DUCT RATTLING]
Your 24 hours has expired.
I need an answer, Troy.
Are you ready to join
the elite brotherhood
who fix air conditioners?
I'm sorry,
Vice Dean Laybourne.
But I realize no one's better
than anyone else.
I mean, some people
are better at sports
and there are magicians,
but I was put on this earth
to do something else.
So you're going to be what?
A plumber?
No, I'm not gonna be
a plumber either.
Because they have
to deal with poop.
My decision for now is
to watch TV with my friend.
You're making a huge mistake.
That may be, sir.
But at least it's my mistake.
Doesn't change the fact
it's a mistake.
Doesn't it?
No, it doesn't.
Sir, there was a malfunction
in the cafeteria last night.
The Amana 5000
had a compound coil fracture.
But it was fixed.
Heh, heh, heh, very funny.
Not even I can fix a compound
coil fracture overnight.
But he can.
Constable Reggie.
Inspector Spacetime.
This isn't over,
Troy Barnes.
It's only just begun.
You know what?
I was wrong.
You'll make
a very good therapist.
And why is that?
You really nailed Pierce
in that whole oedipal thing.
The guy's got
serious father issues.
Don't you think you may have
some oedipal issues as well?
Not seeing the connection.
You literally killed a father.
Yeah, well, not mine, dummy.
Wow.
Hey, Winger.
You going home alone?
Gay!
[♪♪♪]
[IN ENGLISH ACCENT]
That was close,
Constable Reggie.
Those Blorgons
had us dead to rights.
[IN ENGLISH ACCENT]
What on Beta-Earth
do they want from us?
The question's not what they
want from us, but when.
Inspector, look out!
Blorgons!
BLORGON:
Eradicate! Eradicate! Eradicate!
TROY: Unh.
ABED: Pew, pew, pew.
Take that, Blorgon scum.
How old are you guys?
The question
isn't how old we are,
but when old we are.
Ah.
ABED:
In your face, Blorgon twit.
Pew.
Pew, pew, pew.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
What's up, girl?
How you living?
Pew.