[♪♪♪]
I'm glad you're moving out
of this neighborhood, Annie.
Some dude peed on my car
while I was parking it.
Oh, you met Spaghetti.
Yeah, I won't miss him.
Speaking of missing people,
how did Jeff dodge this bullet.
Of friendship.
He was under the weather.
Yeah.
Thanks. Can you imagine
how much fun this is gonna be?
Me living with Troy and Abed?
There'll be a honeymoon phase,
but it won't be long
till you hate their guts.
What's this
little guy's name?
I'll never hate Troy and Abed.
Oh, my God, I forgot. You're 20.
Don't worry. It's natural.
When you become
roommates with friends
the things you love
become the things that
make you wanna smother them.
But that's unacceptable to me.
Then I'm lying?
[DOOR OPENS THEN ABED
IMITATES TRUMPET]
Forgetting something?
Yeah.
Yes!
Hit it.
[PLAYING]
Yeah, like I'm gonna
get sick of this.
What, what?
We're here to help you move
on the dance floor.
Nice. Tweet it.
Tweeting.
What are you tweeting?
TROY: Everything.
We're live-tweeting
Annie's move.
Hashtag: Annie's Move.
How fun.
How was I supposed to know
it was a handicap space?
The man in the wheelchair
was yelling it.
Oh, yeah,
and he doesn't have an agenda.
Hold it.
Where's Winger?
Sick.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm calling him.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
[IN RASPY VOICE] Hello?
BRITTA: So you're sick, huh?
Uh, that's what they tell me.
Cut the wit, Winger.
Where are you,
the Gap or Banana Republic?
Wow, Britta,
you got me all figured out.
I can tell you're not in bed.
That's right, Britta.
I'm pretending
to be violently ill
to avoid lifting a few boxes.
Because I'm 13.
And who's your primary care
physician, Mr. Winger?
Dr. Schroeder. S-C-H.
Do you wanna see
my insurance card?
Please.
Wait, are you at a hospital?
No, I'm at The Gap.
[BARCODE GUN BEEPING]
You hear that?
That's not a heart monitor.
It's a machine telling me
I'm low on khakis.
CLERK [OVER PA]:
Dr. Tarpenian to radiology,
Dr. Tarpenian.
Crap, I'm sorry.
I just assumed--
Whatever. I don't blame you.
I've lied before. It's probably
karma that I'm sick.
But believe me,
if you had what I have,
you'd rather be moving boxes.
Okay, feel better. Sorry.
Yeah, I'll see you guys
on Monday.
[COUGHS]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
You are fantastic.
So are you.
What are you doing after this?
Probably trying
a couple of boot-cuts.
But after that, maybe,
like, a blazer?
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
How are we out of tape?
I don't know.
I think I left some
in the bathroom.
Nope, nothing in here.
You guys. You used all of it?
TROY: I had a big breakfast.
Nice. Tweeting it.
There may be a slight danger
I end up hating them.
Man-children.
Can't live with them,
can't leave them alone
with your tape.
Britta, don't make jokes.
You're bad at it.
Also, I can't afford to live
anywhere else.
And everything is riding on
this, and I'm out of tape--
Annie, listen. Breathe.
When I was in Amsterdam,
I met this guy
who ate too many shrooms,
and fell out of a window
at the Anne Frank House.
Oh, no, no, he's fine.
The doctor said that the drugs
made his body just limp enough
to keep him from
breaking his neck.
Don't see what your taste in men
has to do with my situation.
What I'm saying is
if you're gonna live
with two guys like that,
you've gotta learn to go limp.
Loosey-goosey.
Shake it all up.
Limp. Loosey-goosey.
Okay. New Annie.
Going with the flow.
Loosey-goosey. Is it
loosey-goosey or goosey-loosey?
Is it hyphenated?
You know what? Don't tell me.
I don't need to know.
Broheim.
ABED:
Okay, go.
Didn't feel it.
What a fun use
you found for my bubble wrap.
I know. We have to
sell this to the military.
Yeah, baby. Yeah, baby.
Here's the other tape gun.
Think fast.
ANNIE:
Ohh!
You broke my pluggy thing.
No worries. That's what
the security deposit is for.
Hashtag: That Is All.
No, you're not
letting some slumlord
take your hard-earned money.
I'll fix it. I used to do
that kind of thing
when I was a slumlord.
Really, Pierce? My landlord's
coming by at 5:00.
Think you're gonna have it done?
Easy peasy, George and Weezie.
This is the last
that'll fit in our car.
I'll help you.
But not in an uptight way.
I'm concerned
about this living situation.
I've seen enough
Friends to know
that cohabitation
leads to sex, drugs,
and something called
Schwimmer-fatigue.
Good, Shirley.
What's the saying?
If you can't stop them,
judge them?
Somebody's gotta be
this group's moral compass.
Somebody has to be you?
Because by "moral compass,"
you mean Shirley's religion.
Oh.
Want a ride?
If this is a forecast,
I'll ride with somebody else.
PIERCE:
Don't worry, Shirley.
Keep me company
while I fix this and
I'll give you a ride over there.
SHIRLEY:
Britta!
[♪♪♪]
PELTON:
Well, hey there, stranger.
What a coincidence, huh?
This is just like that
Lake House movie.
I can only assume.
Even I have limits.
Dean Pelton.
Jeff, it's Saturday.
Call me Craig.
Off campus,
I'm just a Craigular Joe. Ohh.
What'd you get? Ahh.
Now I feel like I have to
head back out there.
Dean-- Craig, it's nice to see
you, but I actually have to run.
Oh, yeah, you're probably
heading to help Annie move.
Right?
Oh, I follow
Troy and Abed on Twitter.
Looks like Annie's moving
and you're sick at the hospital?
Curious. I might
head there myself.
I could tell them
you said hi.
I'd rather you didn't.
Well, maybe I won't have time.
Especially
if we're doing lunch?
[SLURPING]
Yeah, but your religion
isn't the same as morality.
And calling me amoral
because I'm atheistic
is religious persecution.
How can I persecute you?
You don't have a religion.
Oh, look. A hitchhiker.
A person in need.
Oh, my God.
What am I doing?
I'm pulling over
to help him out.
Do not help him out.
Why, because it proves the
existence of secular morality?
No, because he looks stinky.
Judge not, Shirley. Judge not.
I really appreciate it,
thank you.
Where are you headed,
fellow human?
Riverside Falls?
That's 40 minutes away.
Oh, I guess I'm just
a really good person.
I knew you were. I could see
the kindness in your faces.
I assume you both accepted
Jesus Christ
as your lord and savior?
Oh, that's nice.
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMS]
Needed a coat of paint anyway.
Welcome, Annie,
to your new home.
Okay. To reacquaint you,
there's the bathroom, kitchen,
and, of course,
ta-da, our bedroom.
Room's a rocking, knock,
because there's something
probably wrong.
Yeah, we're pretty
chill in there.
Mm-hm.
Now let's go see your room.
What's that?
That is your room.
You said this was a two-bedroom.
It is, one, two.
Yours is a blanket fort.
Awesome blanket fort.
But still highly flammable,
so no candles.
What do you think?
Tweet it?
BOTH:
Tweeting it!
[♪♪♪]
I'm not surprised
you're taken aback.
This is where
dreams come true.
We spent our lives
being told blanket forts
are only for
special occasions,
like sleepovers
or when uncles die.
That's a lie, Annie. You can
live in a fort of blankets
all day, every night.
It's so awesome.
Surprised you
haven't chosen to live in one.
We'll be spending time in yours.
It's where we're gonna watch TV.
Right.
[♪♪♪]
And what's that door over there?
That's not a bedroom?
No.
Oh, no, no, no.
Is it a linen closet?
TROY: Something like that.
What's a linen closet?
A siesta salad and an iced tea.
Excelente, and for you?
[CLEARS THROAT]
The gentleman...
Ohh.
...will have a top-notch-os
and a watermelon Margarita.
Thank you, Jeffrey.
So any brothers or sisters?
And we'll take the check too.
Whoa. What's the rush?
We eat lunch, then I'm leaving.
Okay. I just hope
that I don't bump into
your study group on Monday.
And I pray they don't ask me
who I saw at the mall
on Saturday.
Because,
unlike a certain someone,
I just don't think I could lie
to those sweet people.
Dean, this is blackmail.
Call me Craig.
And call blackmail
"a day at the mall with Craig."
Because that's all I require,
Jeffrey.
You and I are going to have some
fun, and create a few memories.
And I suggest you get into it,
because that counts.
A song for the señor, señor?
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Oh, what a surprise.
[PLAYING SOFT MUSIC]
[GRUNTING]
Jeez.
This is actually quite calming
for some reason.
And that's when I realized
I had to forgive them.
That's a beautiful story.
So inspiring
how he came to find the lord.
Isn't it, Britta?
Yeah, yeah.
Well, I didn't exactly have to
find the lord. He was inside me.
Amen. What's your name, friend?
Jesus.
Ohh. Are you Latino?
No, my child. I am him.
You're what now?
I am the one true son of God.
I was sent here
to save humanity.
Oh, no.
Well, it is a pleasure
to have you in my car, Jesus.
Britta, stop.
It's not funny now.
Hey Jesus, just curious, what's
your position on marijuana?
It was given to us by God.
It should be legal.
Oh, that's nice.
Mm-mm.
[♪♪♪]
TROY:
Hear me, hear me.
[ABED IMITATES TRUMPET]
ABED:
Presenting
the real-life fairy tale
of how princess Annie
was saved from Bad Neighborhood
Forest by Woodsman Troy.
And Bebad, his emotionally
unavailable unicorn.
[ABED WHINNIES]
TROY: Brought to you by
the girl-yogurt
Jamie Lee Curtis uses to poo.
[ABED IMITATES FART]
ABED:
A package of it
is in the fridge.
TROY:
Now, once upon a time
there was a beautiful princess
named Annie.
[IN HIGH PITCHED VOICE] Hi.
ABED: Who was harassed every day
by Count Spaghetti.
[ABED CACKLES]
The evil cracksmith who lived
outside of her building.
Whoa! I just stand here?
Oh, come on, Jeffrey.
Get in here.
This is gonna be fun.
Or else.
So we just punch in the numbers?
MAN [OVER PA]: That's right.
Okay, you know this one, Jeff.
We've sang it a thousand times
together in my mind.
[SEAL'S "KISS FROM A ROSE"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Oh, come on, Jeffrey.
Make-or-break time.
Unless you wanna be
back here next Saturday.
♪ There used to be a greying
Tower alone on the sea ♪
♪ You became the light
On the dark side of me ♪
BOTH:
♪ Did you know the light
That you shine can be seen ♪
[PLAYING PIANO]
[TROY BEAT BOXING]
[LAUGHS]
♪ And now that
Your rose is in bloom ♪
♪ A light hits
The gloom on the gray ♪
♪ Jesus loves marijuana ♪
Amen.
JESUS:
♪ Jesus loves marijuana ♪
♪ And drinking human blood ♪
♪ Baby I compare you to a kiss
From a rose on the grave ♪
♪ Ooh, the more I get of you
The stranger it feels, yeah ♪
♪ Now that your rose
Is in bloom
♪ A light hits the ♪
♪ The gloom on the gray ♪
Ha, ha. Ah!
That was great.
Yeah, might have been
a little fun.
See?
And you e-mailed
your therapist
that you wanted to
be alone this weekend.
What?
Hm?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
And now,
with your permission,
I'd like to sing a little song
about race-mixing.
This one's called
"Don't You Do It."
Get out!
[DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS]
Ah, good evening, senator.
Any requests?
What do you wanna do next?
I paid for a full hour, so--
I e-mail my therapist from
my Greendale account.
The same account
where I received
an e-mail from Physique 25
telling me about today's sale.
Is that why you're at the mall?
You read student e-mails?
Now the Patriot Act says I can
do it, Jeffrey, technically.
Need I remind you
the nation is at war?
I'll kill you.
No, Jeffrey, no.
Jeffrey, come on.
Just remember,
we were making memories.
No, Jeffrey, no.
JEFF:
We weren't making anything.
PELTON:
It's too violent.
Don't let the terrorists win!
We weren't making anything.
ABED:
And then the three of them
lived happily ever after.
TROY:
Yay!
ABED:
Bebad became the little dipper.
[ABED WHINNIES]
TROY: The end.
[IN HIGH PITCHED VOICE]
Kiss me, Woodsman Troy.
BOTH:
Muah.
You guys. Living here is
gonna be fun all the time.
Let's make the entire apartment
a fort. I'll get more blankets.
[♪♪♪]
This is a space we reserved
for virtual adventures.
Like a playroom,
but only works in our minds.
We call it the Dreamatorium.
But it's a bedroom.
No, no.
There's only two bedrooms,
including the blanket fort.
This is the Dreamatorium.
All day, I've been jumping
through hoops to fit in.
Including the literal hoops
in front of the toilet.
Yes.
And you guys are hoarding
this second bedroom
as some kind of playroom?
And making me sleep
on a pile of laundry?
We worked hard on that.
It's a blanket fort.
It's an asylum for
half-witted children!
As the only adult
in this apartment,
I am making an ultimatum.
Me or this stupid Dreamatorium.
Dreamatorium is non-negotiable.
Read the lease.
The part added in crayon.
Don't wanna take this to court.
Could be a court
in the blink of an eye.
This doesn't work for me.
From the minute
I joined the group,
I've worried about
how uptight I am,
and how I'm no fun.
I was worried
that I wouldn't fit in here
or be able to hang with you.
But you know what?
Why don't you ever ask
whether you can hang with me?
Why am I always the one that has
to adapt? I'm sick of this crap.
Enjoy your stupid Dreamatorium.
We will!
Because this is
our apartment too.
And just because we're awesome
doesn't mean we're not adults.
Candy cigarette?
I don't want candy.
I want our Annie.
Yeah, we blew it.
I picked the wrong week
to quit.
[♪♪♪]
What the hell is this?
In security deposit terms,
it's a gold mine.
Lucky it's only
gonna cost money.
Your friend nearly
killed himself.
Yeah, that's me. Lucky Annie.
I'm really sorry, Annie.
I had some island girls over
and one of them must have
slipped me a mickey.
I'm just glad you're okay.
You can pay me back
by helping me
get all my stuff
from Troy and Abed's.
You're moving again?
How long was I out?
Is Napster still a thing?
You've been out long enough
for me to realize
that I'm gonna need
to keep living alone.
Come on. Let's get you
cleaned up.
Oh, what the hell?
I have brain damage.
Nothing I do counts.
[♪♪♪]
Where is all my stuff?
Troy, Abed?
It's all yours.
We're sorry. Sometimes we get
stuck in our own little world.
Then in that world,
we make even littler worlds.
And sometimes there are tunnels
between those worlds.
Or a subway.
One time a snake.
We're sorry.
Do you like it?
Of course I do. It's perfect.
I can rearrange
the pillows.
You arranged by size.
What did I say?
But what about the Dreamatorium?
It's more important than us.
You're more important
than our room.
We put the bunk bed
in the blanket fort.
This is all gay code.
You sure I'm worth it?
There's a couple things
we were hoping you'd help with.
Where does water go in the iron?
What's the iron for?
What gets out Kool-Aid stains?
The opposite color Kool-Aid
doesn't work.
Troy scraped me when we were
fork-jousting last week.
I don't think it's healing.
Oh! That's infected.
Infected.
That's the word.
Hi, guys.
I thought you were sick.
I wasn't. I kind of made it up
to get out of helping.
Oh, that's okay.
It is?
Yeah, it is.
Oh, hey, Jeff,
did you know that when
it snows my eyes become large?
ALL:
♪ And the light that you shine
Can be seen ♪
He tweeted it?
♪ Baby ♪
He tweeted it!
PELTON:
♪ And now that
Your rose is in bloom ♪
♪ A light hits
The gloom on the gray ♪
ABED: Oh, look out, asteroids!
TROY: That was close.
TROY:
Thanks for getting us
to planet Greendalia safely,
Horse-bot 3000.
ANNIE:
Oh, no. Greendalia has been
overrun by evil King Blorgon.
ABED: Look out, Troyborg.
[ANNIE IMITATES GUNSHOTS]
ABED: Ahh! I'm dead.
TROY:
Horse-bot 3000, no. I love you.
ABED [IN DEEP VOICE]:
I am King Blorgon.
My plan is to blow up the world.
Your lasers
are useless against me.
TROY:
Aim for his butt.
It's his only weakness.
Bam, bam, bam!
ABED:
Ahh!
ANNIE:
We did it. Peace and tranquility
have been restored
to Greendalia.
TROY:
And all thanks
to Horse-bot 3000.
He belongs to the stars now.
[TROY NEIGHS]
Five minutes and we should
probably put a stop to this.
Jeff, are you--
I liked Horse-bot 3000.