BOY:
Why did I go Greendale?
So I can keep my job and get
busy with my education.
To meet
different people.
Because Greendale's
a slam dunk.
So why should you...
Why should you go Greendale?
That's easy. Greendale has
the most advanced typing class
in the Southwestern area.
And now, you can
register by fax.
ALL:
Go, Greendale!
Go, Greendale, go!
That, as you
probably know,
is the currently-running
commercial.
I see it during late-night
marathons of Fantasy Island.
That's not an accident.
It's the result of targeting.
But now,
Greendale's school board
has given me
a budget of $2,000
to update our little ad.
Are you sure it should change?
I chose Greendale
over City College
because of the way
that one dude goes...
[BOTH GIGGLING]
PELTON: Okay.
I love to be seen
agreeing with you, Troy.
But this is
our chance to make
Greendale's most reasonable
dreams come true.
And I need your help,
all of you.
That's okay, Jeffrey.
You can say no.
This school asks little of
its students. It mainly gives.
I feel like you guys might know
what I'm talking about.
[SIGHS]
[STIFFLY]
How can we help?
Oh, thanks
for asking.
I've chosen you,
Greendale's brightest,
most diverse,
Hispanics notwithstanding,
study group to star
in our commercial.
SHIRLEY: Ooh.
Pick a character.
We start this weekend.
Oh, we get to be on TV!
If we're shooting this weekend,
why are these cameras here?
Abed has decided
to do the weird thing
and film a documentary
instead of helping.
Trying to make this commercial
may cost the Dean his sanity.
My camera follows fire,
not the smoke.
Ever seen Hearts of Darkness?
Way better than Apocalypse Now.
What's the catering sitch
going to be?
This isn't Hollywood. If it was,
these glasses would be tinted,
and I'd be friends with
Stevie Nicks. No catering.
Outrageous. I'm not leaving
my trailer till there's food.
You don't have a trailer.
Then I'll rent a trailer.
And I won't leave it till
I have the one I don't have.
I'm an actor, not a freak.
Oh, no.
I needed to go that way.
Eh, I'll loop around.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
All right, let's rehearse
this mamajama.
Does everyone know
who they are?
Where's my script girl?
Supervisor. I'm behind you.
Thank you,
Supervisor Girl.
Faster than a locomotive.
A Script Supervisor tells
everyone to stay on script
and keeps careful notes to
prevent logical inconsistencies.
So, basically,
the star.
We open on a typical day
at Greendale,
only the students look happy
and you can't smell that smell.
Troy?
"Why do I go Greendale?"
"With three kids, you better
believe every penny counts."
"To meet
different people."
And then, you and Troy hug...
If you're comfortable with that.
Of course.
Troy and I are buds.
Best buds. Air buds, even.
[NERVOUS LAUGHTER]
[MUTTERING]
Feeling stupid.
And then, the camera pans,
and enter Dean Pelton.
JEFF:
I got stuck with
the role of the Dean.
So I'm going to show him
how much of a dean I can be.
And I've got a feeling
I won't make the cut.
[AS DEAN]
Welcome to Dean-dale
Community Colle-dean.
I'm a silly goose.
Honk, honk. Dean-a-lee-doo.
Look at me.
Stop.
This is my sister's outfit.
Jeffrey, stop.
You've hit gold.
Save some for the screen.
All right, people,
Scene Six is up first.
I don't think
Pierce is coming back.
Can someone fill in
as the pencil?
PIERCE:
Pierce, screen
of stage and star,
will not leave this trailer
until he gets a trailer.
I'm not leaving that trailer
until there's catering.
And I'm not eating
the food until...
And action.
[AS DEAN]
Why go Greendale?
Just because, just Dean it!
Dean machine.
Got Dean, got much...
And cut.
Oh, a star is born.
JEFF:
I suggested to the Dean
we shoot my scenes
in front of
the Luis Guzman statue
because the Dean
has no legal right
to broadcast Guzman's image,
which means every shot
will be unusable.
I put a call in to Guzman's
lawyers to alert them.
I'm willing to go the extra
mile to avoid doing something.
Like sex with women.
Shut up. You smell
like Mentholyptus.
What are you doing here?
I'm thinking about
breaking into the TV game.
Since it's apparently
sticking around.
I don't want to wake up
in 30 years
and wonder, "What if?"
"Because this full-time Mama
ain't breaking the bank
with your
expensive tuition."
Okay, cut.
Shirley, the voice.
Can you make it, um...
I thought
it would be more s...
What's another word that
means happy-threatening?
The word he's looking for
is "Sassy."
He better pray
he don't find it.
Get this shot, we are done.
[PHONE VIBRATING]
Your phone is ringing.
Oh.
Dean Deaning.
MAN: Dean Pelton?
How you doing?
It's Luis Guzman.
I hear you're making
a commercial for Greendale,
need permission
to use my face or something?
Well, I, um... Uh...
Why not use
the real thing?
I'm sorry?
I'd love to be
in your commercial.
[GASPS]
Wowee!
A real big-time celebrity
wants to be in my commercial.
[DEEPER VOICE]
Wowee.
A real celebrity
wants to be in my commercial.
Come on down.
That's cool.
But I've got
to finish this movie,
so I can't come for
a couple of weeks, all right?
Mr. Guzman, Luis,
thank you.
And can I just say,
I loved you in...
[SNAPS FINGERS URGENTLY]
In...
[CONTINUES HOLDING ON "N"]
IMDb.
See you soon, man.
[BEEP]
That was tragic.
PELTON:
The students here
mean well, they really do.
But what Greendale has always
needed is a miracle.
This is it.
This is how I get to put
Greendale on the map.
I thought this commercial
was going to be okay.
Well, guess what? It just
officially became great.
Let me give you
a little rundown
of this commercial's
great elements.
Luis Guzman is in it.
I'm sorry,
will you excuse me?
Everyone gather around,
quick announcement.
Come on around.
Everything that we shot
so far is worthless.
I've thrown it out, and
we're starting over tomorrow.
Why?
Because...
Luis Guzman is in
the commercial now, so...
[CROWD MURMURS]
Yeah. For realsies.
Everyone, go home.
I'm rewriting all of your parts.
Except for you. You have
locked into something here.
And the only thing
your character needs
is more screen time.
Great that he got a celebrity,
but why reshoot everything?
ABED:
Perfectionism. The Dean's
first step down a road
that ends
in self-destruction.
That sounds horrible.
Actually, I might end up
taking this to some festivals.
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
[SINGING SCALES]
ABED:
The production has
taken over the school.
Classes are shut down.
The Quilting Club is being
forced to sew costumes.
PELTON: [OVER PA]
Two females, 5'10",
one brunette, one with asthma.
He's also using the PA
for casting calls.
Okay, everyone... Does
everyone have their new script?
Uh, it says I'm supposed
to be a book reading a book.
That doesn't make sense.
[CLEARING THROAT]
What's this?
[GRAVELLY VOICE]
Scene four.
Last night,
I had an epiphany.
I'm ready to step this mother
up a notch.
This commercial is going
to push every button,
starting with the one so hot,
it will sizzle your finger...
Racccccce.
And action.
"To meet
different people."
PELTON:
Cut! I'm coming in.
I am trying to pull
a 400-year-old dagger
out of this nation's heart,
and you two are hugging.
Her, I understand,
but you?
What did I do?
You didn't. Let's take it again!
"To meet
different people."
PELTON: Again.
"To meet different people."
PELTON:
I need more! More!
Wrong! Fight the power! Fight it
with your hugs.
Tear down those walls.
[CLAPBOARD CLACKING]
Get this wrong one more time,
I'm segregating the school.
"To meet
different people."
PELTON:
You can't even do it
when we're helping!
[BOTH SOBBING]
Somebody help her!
To meet different people!
Stop saying I'm different!
Dean, we've spent
12 hours on this scene.
Maybe it's time to move on.
I'm in Psych 101, and even
I don't know what's happening.
ABED:
The Dean is going insane
and taking you with him.
If you know that,
then do something!
ABED:
I'm doing everything I can.
I only have so many cameras.
Oh!
Aah!
JEFF:
I've spent an entire day
in this thing for no reason.
What if the shoot drags on
for another day?
Or, God forbid, two.
[♪♪♪]
PELTON:
And action, and move.
"This mama
ain't breaking the bank..."
Cut, cut, cut ...
Garrett,
you're not taking advantage
of the motion technology.
You have to move.
I forgot what I am again.
Oh, for crying out...
You are a microscope!
No, that's a toilet.
That's clearly a frog
who can't get out of a box.
CHANG:
Jeff thinks he has it bad?
As Jeff's understudy,
I have to wear my Jeff wig
on top of my Chang hair and
my bald cap on top of that.
There's no air getting through.
I'm literally dying.
But you'll never hear my story.
[SCOFFS]
I mean, now you heard it, but...
That was close.
EUGENE [OVER PHONE]:
You sure you can't
work faster?
Nobody asked
for perfection.
Perfection is
what you're getting.
If you don't like it,
fire me.
If we don't like it,
at this point,
we definitely will fire you.
Good!
That's how I like it. Ha!
PELTON:
I'm surrounded by assassins.
My own school's paper
has turned on me.
But when this is all over,
I'll have a commercial
with Luis Guzman in it,
and all they'll have are their
words, and their fears,
and whatever
embarrassing photos
they can get from my mother.
ANNIE:
I've got two men
in diapers here.
I know one is playing the dawn
of a new era in education,
but I've got nothing
on the other.
Just a guest
of the Dean's.
Both of you
go that way, then.
ANNIE:
The Dean had
his seventh epiphany,
which has given me
an epiphany of my own.
The Dean is a genius.
He has to be.
If he isn't, I've given two
weeks of my life to an idiot.
That is unacceptable. Therefore
the Dean is a genius.
And I will die
protecting his vision.
ABED:
Are you familiar
with Stockholm Syndrome?
Something the Dean created?
If not, I don't care.
SHIRLEY:
We wanna go,
but the Dean won't let us.
I think Pierce
played this the smartest.
He's probably watching Forensic
Files and eating popcorn.
Well, about time.
Hey, that's for
Luis Guzman.
When you get me my trailer,
he can have it back.
And make it
as nice as this one.
Hey, Dean.
Dean? Hey, Dean!
JEFF:
Pierce mistook me
for the Dean.
PIERCE: I want windows.
ABED: How did that feel?
[WHISPERING]
I've become a stranger
to myself.
I'm bald now.
I've always been bald.
I merely dreamt
of having hair.
And now the bald man is awake.
Jeff?
It's time.
Lights, camera, Dean.
PELTON:
Action.
Why go Greendale?
Just because!
PELTON:
Cut. Cut.
Lose the bald cap.
What?
I don't like it.
It's hokey, it's fake.
Take it off.
No.
I beg your pardon, actor?
I have worn this stupid thing
for 12 days.
I have made bald friends.
Well, that's your mistake.
Because it's a lie.
It's Hollywood crap.
And I won't allow it
in my commercial.
You're not bald.
Yes, I am.
Well, then, you're wrong
for the part!
Understudy!
[GASPS]
That's it.
That's reality.
Winger, you're done.
Go home.
[SNIFFLING]
[SOBBING]
BRITTA:
I don't know why.
This is the last straw.
As a licensed
psychology major,
I am declaring this production
a violation of human rights.
You have made us prisoners of
your insanity.
Shut your face, Britta.
If the Dean wants his role
to be played by a Chinese man
in a blond wig...
Oh, my God,
you are insane.
I'm sick and tired
of hearing complaints
I'm forcing people
to be here.
Anyone who doesn't want
to help me can leave!
[♪♪♪]
Abed, stop!
ABED:
Okay.
Keep rolling.
Hello? Hello.
Hello?
Hello, it's me.
Luis Guzman.
Hello!
Hi.
Hi, Mr. Guzman,
Dean-Director Craig Pelton.
Sorry, I've been editing.
It's a little bit
of a mess.
[BOTTLES CLANKING]
What the [BLEEP]
is that?
PELTON:
Oh, that's a possum.
Once you spend time
with them,
you see they're just like
big gentle rats.
Who's the guy?
ABED: I'm no one.
That's Abed.
He's a little bit odd.
Now, without
further ado,
here is the commercial
you will be starring in.
[INDISTINCT CELTIC MUSIC]
JEFF: [ON TAPE]
Why do I go Greendale?
[DISCO MUSIC]
[PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[HEAVY METAL MUSIC]
[SINGER SCREAMING]
MAN:
What's in the box?
[CLASSICAL MUSIC]
WOMAN: Oh! Oh!
[OVERLAPPING SOUND EFFECTS]
[DANCE MUSIC]
[TAPE STOPS]
I got to make a phone call.
I had to tell this dean
I couldn't do his commercial.
He didn't take that
too well either.
Y'all gotta help this dude.
Aren't you his friends?
ABED:
I'm more of
a fly on the wall.
What is go...
What?
You won't be
in my commercial,
but you'll be in
his stupid documentary?
All he does
is follow people.
Haven't you seen
Hearts of Darkness?
Way better than...
I want you off my campus.
I already got rid
of your trailer.
I had a trailer?
PIERCE:
Can anyone hear me?
I will walk off this production.
I will quit!
Hello?
I come here to shoot this
for Greendale.
That's what you had
on the script.
That script was terrible.
I thought it was good.
Of course
you'd think that.
You went here.
Oh, I get it.
You're worse
than crazy.
You're ashamed
of your school.
And that statue of me,
that's just wrong, man.
The bronze adds 10 pounds.
Nah, man...
It's not going to be perfect.
Screw you.
I'm just saying,
don't worship the people leaving
Greendale.
Worship the people
that are here.
Worship this place.
It changes people's lives.
Look, I loved my time here.
I got laid like crazy.
That's way before
Boogie Nights, too.
Look, this is
a special school.
You don't deserve to be here.
[SCOFFS]
Are you still
filming, Abed?
ABED:
Yeah. Try not to address me.
I'm not here.
Neither am I.
I don't think I can finish
my commercial.
But I think I know how
your documentary ends.
[♪♪♪]
Hi, I'm Craig Pelton, Dean
of Greendale Community College.
I have failed
this school.
I have failed because I thought
I was better than Greendale.
See, I went
to a university,
so I thought it was my job
to improve this place.
It turns out the only thing
wrong with Greendale
is that it's run
by an insecure wreck
who holds five dances
and two talent shows a year
because he's afraid
the school isn't good enough.
But Greendale
is good enough
because it accepts me
for what I'm not.
[SNIFFLING]
Greendale is the best school
in the entire world,
and I'm so sorry
what I've done to it.
And I'm sorry what I've done
to the ice-cream machine.
[SCREAMING]
Please, no one eat out of it
until you clean the nozzles.
The janitor knows how.
I'm horrible.
[WHISPERS]
What I'm about to show you
is not the commercial
you paid me to create.
What I am about
to show you
is a glimpse into
my mind and soul.
Hold your questions
until the end.
I know you will have
a lot of them,
but I'll understand
if you'd rather I just leave.
[UPBEAT CHEESY POP MUSIC]
TROY: Why do I go Greendale?
The Dean is a genius.
BRITTA:
To meet different people.
SHIRLEY:
With three kids,
every penny counts.
I loved my time here.
I got laid like crazy.
GIRL: Why should you...
BOY 1: Why should you...
BOY 2:
Why should you go
to Greendale?
Greendale is the best school
in the entire world.
ALL:
Go, Greendale!
Go, Greendale, go!
It's good. You know what?
Better than good.
Good enough.
Is there more of the crazy
Chinese guy? He pops.
I'm confused. That's not my
commercial. I didn't make that.
Yeah, okay, Zemeckis,
it moved through you.
Anyway,
congratulations.
That should last us
another 16 years.
So, uh, what's next?
Chump's Rusty Bucket?
Quarter taps.
Did you do this?
ABED: You did mostly.
You got the footage
on the first day.
I added a little bit
to fill in the gaps.
I thought you were
a fly on the wall.
Some flies are
too awesome for the wall.
Documentarians are
supposed to be objective,
to avoid having
any effect on the story.
Yet we have more effect
because we decide to tell it.
And decide how it ends.
Will your story be
another sad one
of another man
who wanted to be happy?
Or will your story acknowledge
the very nature of stories
and embrace
that sharing the sad ones
can sometimes
make them happy?
Ugh! Before you say
anything...
Nope, I've got nothing.
Can you just forgive me?
Yep.
[RELIEVED SIGH]
Why?
Because we've all
been there.
Which is why
we're all here.
ALL:
Aww!
I'm a good dean?
Yeah.
Can someone help me get a live
possum out of my office?
We could do that.
It just keeps
jumping and skittering.
And you think you're prepared,
and then it skitters again.
Okay, scene's over.
Hmm?
[BOTH LAUGH]
[EXCITING PREMIERE-LIKE
MUSIC]
They'll be ready for you
in 20 minutes.
Great.
I'm a star!
Give me that.
I will not be mitigated.
Okay, you know what?
I'm not coming
out of this trailer
until I get
a new trailer.
And get me
a granola bar!