Pierce!
Hi!
Hi, Pierce. Oh...
Hi.
Hey.
Happy New Year, you guys.
Do anything fun over break?
Baby Ben got to be Baby Jesus
in our church's Nativity play.
Andre was Joseph,
Jordan, one of the Wise Men,
and I was in charge
of casting.
I digitized my entire movie
collection. Goodbye, VHS.
Hello, SelectaVision
CED Video Disc.
I'm very psyched
for the new semester.
Or should I say...
Intro to Human Psyched.
[ALL GROAN]
The worst.
For our midterm,
we actually get to diagnose
a fellow student
with something.
Don't you do that already?
Accusational
Opposition Disorder.
Hello.
Whoa.
You've noticed my swagger
has a new swagger.
I'll explain. Over break,
I took the plunge
and started seeing a new shrink.
What? Hello!
Hello. I talked about my dad,
punched a few pillows.
And she put me on this
amazing anti-anxiety pill.
It's really enhanced
my self-confidence.
I explained that
really well.
Jeff, you can't be
on anti-anxiety meds.
What self-doubt you have
is the only thing
keeping your ego
penned in.
You are a textbook
narcissist.
I'm an exceptional
narcissist, Britta.
Oh, excuse me.
I didn't kill my wife!
I don't care.
[♪♪♪]
Stop that fugitive!
I was wondering how long for
things to get back to normal.
Over break,
Abed realized he could hire
celebrity impersonators
for his own personal use.
He's been doing it a lot.
He's not hurting anybody.
He likes reenacting scenes
from movies.
It's unquestionably awesome.
I question it.
He spent New Year's
with Tom Hanks from Cast Away.
Abed was the volleyball?
That makes sense.
You guys, focus!
Where's he getting the money?
Intervention. Intervention.
No! You guys need to stop.
You seriously have a problem.
I said I didn't kill my wife!
I still don't care.
Freeze!
[ALARMED CRIES]
Chang, they're just acting!
Oh. Sorry.
WOMAN: What was that?
I've got a friend
at the zoo.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some more
Time in a dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
What is this I hear
about a tranquilizer gun?
If you had hit a small student,
they could have died!
I wouldn't. I have
a heavy flashlight for them.
Oh, Ben!
Look,
I have to resort
to extreme measures.
I'm a one-man army. You won't
let me have any guards.
We're broke! We get
80 percent of our electricity
from the apartment building
across the street.
Okay. I don't know who told you
pouting was an option for you,
but all you're making me feel
is hatred of Renee Zellweger.
Look, maybe you bring on some
students as security interns.
I'll let you offer them
a credit in safety or math.
Thank you. You won't regret this
unless I rise up against you.
I don't know why
I said that. Bye.
Huh! Tah!
Zhou! Zeet! Dah! Toi!
Jeff. Jeff!
I looked it up.
I was right.
About Danny Thomas?
I looked it up too. Weird.
No, those meds
you're taking.
Without anxiety to keep
your vanity in check,
you are vulnerable
to Hypernarcissosis.
Okay, look.
This apple is your ego.
Imagine it expanding
to the point of critical mass,
taking over
your whole personality,
making you
an uncontrollable monster.
How did an apple make that
clear? Imagine it expanding?
Use a balloon.
I'm on my way to lunch.
Why take this away from me?
I like having no anxiety.
I'm in harmony with the world.
Looking good, Winger.
Thank you for that compliment,
and for your service
to this country.
I'm so confident I can pull
things off I never dreamed.
Look. Aviators.
Final boarding call,
Beefcake Airways.
I'm warning you as your friend
to get off of those meds.
Until they're out
of your system,
stay away from flattering
situations, weddings,
soft lighting,
formal wear, gay bars.
And take those off!
Because they make me look good?
That's not relevant.
Ah, welcome back, Jeffrey.
How was your...
Uh-huh-hunh!
[GASPING]
Oh, my God! Even his shadow!
Look at his shadow!
[GASPS]
[SPASMS]
[♪♪♪]
Security internship
available.
Come on, see the world.
You won't see the world,
but come on!
Hey, Nadir.
Oh, hey, Vinnie.
Vinnie's the owner of the
celebrity impersonator service.
You look familiar.
That's how we all get started.
But at a certain point,
if you're smart,
you move up to management
before the gold mine
of resembling French Stewart
runs dry.
ALL: Ah...
French Stewart...
Speaking of gold mines,
you owe me three grand, pal.
Cool. Put it on my account.
Do I look like a sucker?
French Stewart.
I don't have three grand.
Better get it. Because
I'll tell you something...
You'd make
an amazing Seacrest.
Very kind. Thank you.
You're actually a lot taller.
You've actually got
a sharper jaw too.
You're more handsome than the
guy famous for being handsome.
[JEFF GRUNTS]
Jeff?
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
You'll be okay.
Just stay humble.
Maybe there's another option.
I've got a big event
Saturday,
needs a lot
of bodies, huh?
And I see some high-value
faces here. Got an Oprah.
Oh!
And sitting next to her
is a Judy Garland
or an Anne Hathaway.
Add a few extra teeth.
Wow, this is rare. Both
versions of Michael Jackson.
And you...Fat Brando.
Burt Reynolds.
What?
Fat Brando. Whatever.
Burt Reynolds. Whatever.
If you guys
work this gig for me
for six hours,
we'll call it even.
Sounds fun.
Can we have a minute to talk?
Sure. The guy
who makes fish sticks
looks like Quincy Jones.
Get out.
Seriously.
Guys, I'm sorry,
but we have
to put our foot down.
She has a point. Next time
it'll be $10,000, then 20,
then he'll hit rock bottom
and have no one but Jesus.
I say we let this play out.
I'd love to help,
but playing Ryan Seacrest
at a big party
may not be a safe
situation for me.
We could actually hurt Abed
if every time he faces reality,
we play make-believe
to bail him out.
Shame on you people.
It's not our job
to help Abed grow up.
Abed doesn't need reality.
Abed is a magical, elflike man
who makes us all more magical
by being near us.
Pierce, who came over that time
you forgot how to fart?
Abed.
Shirley...
Who got you a DVD of Precious,
based on Push, by Sapphire,
and a copy of Push
autographed by Sapphire?
Abed.
All we had was reality before.
He's made all of our lives
better than reality.
Now it becomes inconvenient,
and it's time to get real?
For shame!
He's right.
Sorry, Troy.
Hey, guys.
Abed, we would be happy
to help you out.
It'll be a good time.
Cool. Cool, cool, cool.
Cool. Oprah.
Oh, thank you.
See ya, Vin.
Fat Brando.
Burt Reynolds.
Yeah.
Thanks for being flexible.
This'll be fun.
Fun. Yeah, sure.
But here's the deal.
Um, if you guys
mess this up,
then his debt is overdue.
And I don't send
another bill.
No, I send two guys
that look a lot
like Ving Rhames
and Michael Chiklis.
And they do a very
convincing impression
of breaking your friend's legs.
Their secret is,
they actually break them.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
Impersonators, our guest of
honor is one Howie Schwartz,
who, according to the Talmud,
just became a man.
But I wouldn't want him
next to me in a foxhole.
Ha!
Ground rules,
do stay in your
assigned quadrants
quoting lines from movies
you are positive
your impersonatee was in.
Do not leave your quadrant,
burp, fart, cough,
hiccup, or cuss.
The exception being James,
our resident Walter Matthau.
How you doing, Jimmy?
[BELCHES]
Give 'em hell.
All right, let's go.
All my life
I has to fight.
Ready to tangle.
Handsome Seacrest,
I need you in this tux.
Jeff, do not wear that.
Aw, zip it, White Jacko.
Don't worry, that thing in
the cafeteria freaked me out,
so my shrink
doubled my dosage.
What?
Jeff, that's insane!
I thought so too, but after
I took that extra pill,
it seemed like a great idea.
Jeff, put it on. Go.
No, Jeff!
Stop arguing. If you have
anything else to say,
say it in a high-pitched
voice walking backwards.
[HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
Jeff is in danger. Hee-hee!
Uh, may I help you?
I'm one of the impersonators.
Which one?
Do I have to say it?
Burt Reynolds.
I don't believe
anybody hired you
to impersonate
Burt Reynolds.
Why not?
Do I have to say it?
May I help you?
I'm Brando.
Hmm...
Could be under "Fat."
Ah. Oh.
[CHUCKLES]
Totally.
Go on in.
[CHUCKLES]
Bam.
Get back to your station.
I'm talking to Geena Davis.
Do this right or
Vinnie won't clear your debt.
Who cares about money? Look
around. This is why we're alive.
Ooh, fake Lorenzo Lamas.
Let's go.
I was so sad to hear
of your passing.
Me too.
Sergeant Chang,
what are you doing here?
Hey, Annie.
Just one of the perks
when your brother's a rabbi.
He throws me some
private security gigs
at the events
he officiates.
They can get really intense
sometimes.
Can you believe some jerk
brought a scalpel to a bris?
MAN:
Now smile.
Why is he out
of his quadrant?
[DEEP VOICE]
I'm Lorenzo Lamas.
He's reenacting a movie.
Please.
What were Jamie Lee Curtis
and Lorenzo Lamas in together?
I'm embarrassed because you've
never seen Lorenzo's Oil.
Lorenzo is an oil tycoon
that gets his address book
switched with
Jamie Lee Curtis',
and they give each other
piggyback rides.
Tch. I can't believe--
Did you go to college?
Yes. No.
Whatever. Keep working.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, my God.
You are gorgeous!
Look at this one.
He's like a Robert Redford.
No, no, more like a taller,
hotter Ryan Seacrest.
Amazing.
You're more handsome
than the guy who's famous
for being handsome.
[♪♪♪]
Skull Cracker 2000.
Top of the line.
Who wants to hold it?
Me!
That's so cool.
Awesome.
Dude, this is so sick.
Check this out.
Any of you young men interested
in a college credit?
Sure!
Right!
[CHUCKLES]
Look, if you have a request,
not a real DJ.
These are props.
You look like a friend.
You're friends with Moby?
[SOLDIERS CHANTING]
[BELL CHIMES]
♪ All the pretty horses ♪
Jeff!
Oh!
[GASPS]
I haven't been dipped like
that since my last divorce.
Britta, you were right.
I can feel my ego taking over.
Do something!
Okay, listen to me.
You are not that big of a deal.
Do you understand?
You have bad posture.
When you do to many pushups,
it looks like you have boobs.
The tile in your bathroom
is tacky.
You were emotionally
closed off in bed
to the point where
I didn't come up
because I couldn't find
close enough parking.
You have an unusually
high butt crack.
Thank you.
It couldn't have been
easy to lie.
We are getting you
out of here.
Get back to
your quadrant. Now!
Britta!
You were the highlight
of the evening.
If it were up to me,
you'd win every award.
There's awards?
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and non-gentilemen,
welcome to Howie Schwartz's
Star Mitzvah Awards.
Here to present
the first award
are Fake Morgan Freeman
and Fake Bono.
You know, Fake Bono,
algebra can be tough.
It sure can,
Fake Morgan Freeman.
And that's why
it's so important
to reward those to whom
it comes so easily.
The winner for
best math student is...
Howie Schwartz.
[APPLAUSE]
Wow, these things are heavy.
[LAUGHTER]
FAKE SEAN CONNERY:
The award for cleanest room
goes to Howie Schwartz.
FAKE CHRISTOPHER WALKEN:
Coolest skateboard trick,
Howie Schwartz!
FAKE JACK NICHOLSON:
Best Halo score,
Howie Schwartz!
[APPLAUSE]
You're gonna win the award for
most handsome young man.
Nah. Oh, give me a break.
It's his bar mitzvah.
Jeff, I think
that we should go.
There's an award
for most handsome young man!
Hello, everyone.
It is my honor and privilege
as Fake Oprah Winfrey
to present the final award.
Most handsome young man.
ALL:
Aw...
And the winner is...
Howie Schwartz!
No!
[PAINED GROAN]
[JEFF GROWLING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Aah!
[CROWD BOOING]
[GROWLING CONTINUES]
Look at me! Look at me!
No, Jeffrey!
Jeffrey... Oh!
Oh!
[CROWD GASPS]
Oh, God, no!
What the hell?
You wanted it!
You all want it!
[GROWLING]
[BOYS SHOUTING]
[ROARS]
[SCREAMS]
Ow!
Ah!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[GROWLING CONTINUES]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
I love you, Dad! I knew
you'd invite the Hulk!
You're lucky.
And your friend's debt is paid.
Hey, Jimmy, wait up.
[BELCHES]
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
Boogie Nights.
You're Fat Burt Reynolds,
right?
I'll take it.
Abed, your leg! What'd they do?
Tell me who they looked like!
[A LA ROBIN WILLIAMS]
Doc, doc! Who's there?
Your femur bone.
He needs money. He's broke.
Ha, ha, ha. Hey.
[ABED CHUCKLES]
Laughter's
the best medicine.
What are you doing?
I'm challenging
your medical establishment.
Not you.
So we just spent our whole night
paying off your debt,
and you're blowing money
on Patch Adams?
It's two for one.
We're doing Popeye next.
[A LA POPEYE]
Ah-ga-ga-ga-ga.
Get him some spinach.
I'm Olive Oyl.
[♪♪♪]
Get out!
Are you mad at me?
No.
Cool.
Gonna go in the Dreamatorium
and play Inspector Spacetime.
Have fun.
Abed.
Yeah?
Come here.
I am mad at you.
You said you weren't.
We never lie.
I know.
We made a deal. Friends
don't lie to each other.
I know! I lied.
You don't like people
who tell you what to do,
and I don't want to.
Then don't be.
I have to be.
Stop renting impersonators.
Vinnie was gonna break
both of your legs.
I had to work hard
to help you.
That's what you wanted to do.
Yes.
But I can't do
what I want to do?
I guess not.
Not all the time.
Sometimes you have
to trust I know better.
I don't know if I can.
Then you're gonna have to trust
that you're gonna have
to trust me.
Well, I don't want to stop
being your friend, so...
I guess I'll let you tell me
what to do sometimes.
Still best friends?
Yeah.
Still best friends.
Always.
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
Still gonna go
to the Dreamatorium?
Think I'm gonna play myself,
if that's okay.
Cool. Okay.
Cool.
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
Seacrest Hulk,
you're the greatest!
Whoo!
You rock, Seacrest Hulk!
[HORN HONKING]
WOMAN:
I love you, Seacrest Hulk!
MAN 2:
You know, Seacrest Hulk,
you're a meshugeneh.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[ENGINE SHUTS OFF]
You okay?
No. I ruined
a bar mitzvah.
I'm a bad person.
What you're feeling
is called shame.
It means you're
getting better.
You'll be safe again
once those pills wear off.
Um, I was thinking...
You know that person you study
for your psych class?
Maybe that should be me.
Uh-uh. No way. You are way
out of my league diagnostically.
I'm gonna go with someone
less complicated. Like Abed.
[MACHINERY WHIRRING]
[SPACESHIP ENGINES RUMBLING]
Hi, Abed.
Hi.
Where's Troy?
In the other room.
That's okay.
There are advantages
traveling by yourself.
You can drive faster,
change direction.
The only pee breaks
are yours.
Are you real?
Are you?
This is really crazy.
And inaccessible,
and maybe too dark.
Maybe to them,
but not to us.
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
Hot.
Hot, hot, hot.
[♪♪♪]
[MILITARY BUGLE PLAYING]
Gentlemen, who's ready
to Chang the world?
KIDS:
Chang! Chang! Chang!
Chang! Chang!
BOY:
All hail Chang!