NARRATOR:
"Between two groups of people
"who want to make inconsistent
kinds of worlds,
I see no remedy but force."
Oliver Wendell Holmes.
SHIRLEY:
There was a point
where all I saw were feathers.
Then I started swinging.
And then I hit something
and heard someone fall.
Could've been somebody
from my side.
NARRATOR:
In 2012,
Greendale Community College
was the site of the largest
and longest pillow fight
in community college history.
It shaped and scarred
the landscape of their campus
and forever changed the lives
of those involved.
[♪♪♪]
A health-care administration
student
who turned a storage room
into a sanctuary
for soldiers
with broken glasses
and lightly grazed testicles.
A high school dropout
and amateur photographer
whose borrowed camera captured
some of the war's blurriest,
most poorly framed moments.
A disgraced former lawyer
whose words would inspire
tens of students
to take up pillows and fight,
most likely to avoid
an upcoming test.
A loving wife and mother who
would prove to be as skilled
at kicking asses
as she was at wiping them.
The dried-up heir
to a moist towelette empire
who would prove to be
the dried-up heir
to a moist towelette empire.
The sensitive
high school quarterback
who became commander-in-chief
of his own army.
He would later say of the war,
"It was awesome,
but also, it wasn't."
And his socially dysfunctional
best friend
turned bitter rival,
an uncompromising tactical
mastermind feared by all,
yet unable
to pay parking tickets
or know left from right
without mouthing
the Pledge of Allegiance.
The rift in their friendship
would carry the school into
a conflict lasting days,
costing hundreds of dollars
and resulting
in over 12 transfers.
SHIRLEY:
There are people who say,
"I don't get it.
So it was a pillow fight."
To which I say:
"You weren't there."
Jeffrey, you have to come
mediate Troy and Abed.
They look up to you.
What's with the film crew?
Don't worry.
If there's one thing
I've learned at this place,
it's that a film crew
means disaster.
They are here to document
Greendale's Guinness Record,
which you are
gonna make sure we get
by talking to Troy and Abed.
This is your fault.
No.
Your fault.
Okay, I've got
good news for you.
Neither of you has to apologize,
what you're doing is ridiculous.
So here's the solution
I'm pitching:
I'm giving you two
imaginary friendship hats
that automatically make you
friends again. Are we done?
Jeff, this matter's a little
more serious than that.
JEFF:
No, it's not. You're children
acting like grown-ups.
Fine. Don't pretend
it's anything but that.
NARRATOR:
Troy Barnes and Abed Nadir,
friends so close,
they once graced the cover
of Friends Weekly, a pretend
magazine of their own design.
Earlier that day,
they begin construction
on a fort made of pillows.
Its name: New Fluffytown.
Its goal: to be a newer,
fluffier town than Fluffytown,
their blanket fort
from the previous year.
HARRY:
New Fluffytown
didn't care who you were.
You were surrounded by
softness.
It's just like
crawling through a hug.
Well, I guess all hugs
have to come to an end.
When an opportunity arises
for a world record,
it creates a rift.
Troy wants to
go for the record,
using blankets
for rapid expansion.
Abed insists on pillows,
declaring world records
to be dumb.
Troy declares
the declaration lame,
stating that thinking records
are dumb is stupid.
He secedes from New Fluffytown
and begins constructing
Blanketsburg
on the other side of campus.
Abed renames his fort
Pillowtown
for the sake of
conceptual symmetry.
Both forts expand until both
are in each other's way.
Study Room F, 3 p.m.,
things reach
their boiling point.
STAR-BURNS:
You stand back.
PELTON: Watch it, Star-Burns.
My name is Alex!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
A softly lobbed,
hypoallergenic Sealy Select
in a floral print case
collides with a load-bearing
broomstick,
collapsing a queen-sized
section of blanket fort.
MAN:
You saw that?
They knocked it down.
[ALL YELLING]
Star-Burns, go.
STAR-BURNS: Excuse me, please.
Hold. Hold.
Jeffrey. Jeffrey, find me.
TROY: Get back.
PELTON: Jeffrey!
NARRATOR:
It was later named
the Study Room Kerfuffle.
ABED:
Protect Pillowtown.
Jeffrey. You're not mediating.
Dean, what do you want me
to say, huh?
Some conflicts
are so pointless,
they have to
play themselves out.
Fine. The Legit Republic
of Blanketsburg
says Pillowtown
has until midnight
to surrender its territory.
The United Forts of Pillowtown
declines the request.
It's not a request.
I'm giving you an "all tomato."
You give me the whole tomato
or else.
Or else what?
[♪♪♪]
See you at midnight.
Oh, my God.
Do people go to classes?
NARRATOR:
The deadline divides
friendships,
families, even study groups.
Pierce Hawthorne
takes Troy's side,
citing that Abed is weirder
and more foreign.
Shirley Bennett decides
her allegiance
in a text message
to her husband.
[SHIRLEY READING TEXT MESSAGE]
NARRATOR:
Troy appoints Shirley Bennett
as his second-in-command,
at which point
Pierce switches to Abed's side.
There were those who thought
midnight might come and go.
Nothing would happen. Heh.
Well, I was in Korea.
And I knew the sound of crap
about to hit the fan.
You know what it sounded like?
That's right, Jackson.
Silence.
NARRATOR:
Midnight comes,
and a campus holds its breath.
MAN [ON RADIO]:
There's a lot of blanket
stackers
and pillow packers
thinking it's gonna go down.
But there's a lot of us folks
from the scene
in between saying:
"Hey,
we're looking to chill out,
and lay down
with someone special."
This is Real Neil
with pipes of steel,
signing off with the smooth
sounds of "Daybreak."
[MICHAEL HAGGINS' "DAYBREAK"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
I gotta get this on film.
I'm straight trouncing Spaz
in Go Fish.
What are you doing?
Don't record this.
MAN: Hey, come on.
Wait, did you hear that?
[PEOPLE YELLING]
Oh, my God.
MAN: What the hell is that?
NARRATOR:
12:07 a.m.,
Blanketsburg soldiers charge a
pillow fort in the library.
The Pillowtonians move quickly
to defend.
SHIRLEY:
There were no rules in that
first battle.
You hit someone,
and if they went down,
you stop hitting them.
Call that common courtesy.
Then what if they get up?
Do you maybe keep hitting them
till they learn to stay down?
We call that common sense.
NARRATOR:
The battle lasts six minutes.
No territory changes hands.
ABED:
Blanketsburg
has drawn first blood.
Pillowtown will draw
First Blood, Part II.
TROY [OVER PA]:
Citizens of Blanketsburg,
I ask you now
to prepare for war.
And I ask Garrett to please fix
the microphone on my laptop.
It's doing that thing again.
NARRATOR:
The United Forts of Pillowtown
and the Legit Republic
of Blanketsburg are at war.
Each side attempting to kick
down and replace the other.
The unmoving line
between them
is a campus-wide,
fleece-laden strip
of pillow-to-pillow combat.
Britta Perry attempts
to capture
the war's sublime indignities
on film.
Unfortunately for Britta
and photographers like her,
just because something
is in black and white
doesn't mean it's good.
Rules are agreed upon,
but casualties are inevitable.
[YELLING AND GRUNTING]
Outside the science lab,
at the Battle
of Big Bulletin Board,
Pierce Hawthorne suffers
broken glasses, a hurt finger
and erectile dysfunction.
Which, in his words,
had never happened
ever before that battle.
WOMAN:
Pillows, but no sleep
Feathers, but no birds
Pajamas without children
Violence without purpose
I saw Mommy kissing Exxon Mobil
Amanda Johnson. Poet by choice,
lesbian by birth.
NARRATOR:
Even Jeff Winger, who, before
the war, lacked interest,
has now found a leading role.
JEFF:
Soldiers of Blanketsburg,
we fight not because
we want war.
We fight that
we might gain peace.
CROWD: Yeah!
Winger's critics suggest
he merely improvised
hot-button patriotic dogma
in a Ferris Buellerian attempt
to delay schoolwork.
Winger decries the accusation
as, quote:
"A slanderous betrayal
akin to 9/11," unquote.
Later, after the war,
he would refer to the theory
as essentially accurate.
Annie Edison provides
humanitarian relief
for both sides.
Her text conversations with
Jeff Winger give us a glimpse
beneath the cushions of war
to the lost pennies
and grody Q-tips
of war's emotional toll.
[♪♪♪]
ANNIE:
Jeff, heard from
one of Troy's soldiers
about a speech you gave
to troops at the fort.
Wish this war could be over,
but proud of you
for taking a stance.
Text message, Annie Edison.
JEFF:
Thank you, Annie. I'm proud of
you too, and of us all.
Also wish
the nightmare would end,
using what I'm given
to give what I can.
Jeff Winger.
ANNIE: Jeff,
just heard from one of Abed's
soldiers that you gave
an identical speech to troops
at Pillowtown.
W-T-F? Sad face. Special icon
of a downward thumb.
JEFF:
Annie, okay, you caught me.
I prefer war to homework.
How do you do
that little thumb icon?
I can't find it on my phone.
Jeff Winger.
[ANNIE READING TEXT MESSAGE]
ANNIE:
Piece of sushi,
birthday cake, stop sign,
snowman, umbrella.
Annie Edison.
NARRATOR:
Pierce Hawthorne,
humiliated in the Battle
of Big Bulletin Board,
wants a chance
to redeem himself.
I've been working on something.
Look at this.
You can build this?
If you'd just give me
the pillows.
I hope to God
we'll never have to use it.
Oh, me too.
NARRATOR:
Rumors of Hawthorne's weapon
find their way to Troy.
Troy Barnes will take no
chances. He turns to Ben Chang,
Greendale's chief of security,
rumored to be literally
psychotic,
and who has been kept on the
sidelines until this moment.
[SITAR MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
BOY:
Attack!
[ALL YELLING]
[♪♪♪]
Chang has recruited an army
of preteen security interns
while moonlighting
at a local bar mitzvah.
They were later nicknamed
The Changlourious Basterds,
like Inglourious Basterds,
but with Chang instead of "In."
I don't get it either.
Most of the soldiers in this war
hadn't fought with
a pillow in years.
These little bastards,
pillow fighting
was a way of life for them.
ANNIE:
One of the injured
said they were making
necklaces out of mattress tags.
Things get as
ugly as they can get
while still being
a pillow fight.
JEFF:
Crazy war, huh?
I heard Chang's kids
are really ducking stuff up.
Hey, check it out.
I downloaded that thing.
Birthday cake, birthday cake,
unicorn, woman's shoe.
How's the nurse thing going?
ANNIE: No response.
[WOMAN SOBBING]
You like pillows?
How do you like these pillows?
NARRATOR:
The Changlourious Basterds
have turned the war
into a chaotic sea
of high-thread-count terror.
Under advice
from his top general,
Abed sees no choice but to
unleash his doomsday device.
[SOBBING]
[GRUNTING]
PIERCE:
You're gonna die,
you little [BLEEP] bastards!
BOY 1:
What the heck is that?
NARRATOR:
He is part-man, part-pillow,
all carnage.
[BOYS SCREAMING]
Pierce Hawthorne
has transformed himself
into an unstoppably plush
juggernaut.
BOY 2:
Guys, guys, just retreat.
Go, go!
ABED:
The war won't stop
with First Blood, Part II.
It will escalate to Rambo III.
Which should be called Rambo
II: First Blood, Part III.
But the Rambo titles
never made sense.
And neither does war.
Abed Nadir,
Facebook status update.
LEONARD:
Leonard likes this post.
[♪♪♪]
Why are you ignoring me?
What's the point?
Words don't mean anything.
They're things you say
to get what you want.
Well, that's
what conversation is, Annie.
People saying things
to get stuff.
Then maybe
you should just shut up.
Do you ever just write stuff
down in a journal, Jeff?
One you don't show people
or use to get anything with?
A place that's just for you
to sort out the truth?
If I write stuff down
in a Hello Kitty book,
will you like me again?
I'm taking that as yes.
NARRATOR:
The war brings out the worst
in people.
Worse yet, Troy's forces
intercept an e-mail
written by Abed
to his commanders,
outlining Troy's weaknesses.
[ABED READING E-MAIL]
ABED:
He gets distracted
by loud noises,
the color red, smooth jazz,
shiny things, food smells,
music boxes,
bell-bottoms, boobs, dogs,
anyone saying, "Look."
[ABED READING E-MAIL]
His greatest vulnerability
is his emotional frailty.
It's incredibly easy
to make him cry,
and he's ashamed of that.
Get away!
NARRATOR: Unfortunately,
the only photographer there
to capture the scene
is Britta Perry.
Yeah, gee.
There's a good one.
Pictured here lying down,
Troy's does not take Abed's
e-mail lying down.
TROY:
Hey, dick, read your dumb
e-mail. Really enjoyed it.
Guess what. You may have been
my best friend,
but we both know
I was your first friend.
What you don't know
because you have mental issues
is that you're never going
to have another friend,
because, all caps,
nobody else will ever have
my patience with you.
Troy Barnes.
Four-part text message.
These two were hurting
each other's feelings.
And I thought
about what Annie said,
and then I thought about what I
might do to make things right.
NARRATOR:
At 8 p.m. of the second night,
both sides
are honoring a cease-fire
so that the infantry can watch
the hit TV show
Ski, Shoot, Sing,
a combination biathlon
singing competition,
no fun to watch time-shifted,
because you'd be the last
to know who won.
During the cease-fire,
Jeff summons Troy and Abed
to a secret summit meeting.
This has to stop.
Tell him.
What about your e-mail?
You weren't supposed
to think those things.
Guys, look at yourselves.
You didn't used to be like this.
You were Troy and Abed.
Things used to be easy.
He's right.
Our friendship is dead.
What?
We should agree that
whoever wins this war
can stay in the apartment.
Loser has to find a new place.
Agreed.
Uh, I wanted that
to go different.
[♪♪♪]
NARRATOR:
The North Cafeteria, named
after Admiral William North,
is located in the western
portion of East Hall,
gateway to the western half
of North Hall,
named not after William North,
but for its position above
the south wall.
It is the most contested
and confusing battlefield on
Greendale's campus,
next to English Memorial
Spanish Center,
named after English Memorial,
a Portuguese sailor
that discovered Greendale
while looking for a fountain
that cured syphilis.
In a fit of hurt feelings,
Troy redirects most of his
infantry to the cafeteria.
They arrive at the same time
as a hundred Pillowtown troops.
[♪♪♪]
Just after dawn,
the end of the war begins.
MAN:
Here we go!
[♪♪♪]
[SHIRLEY YELLS]
[ALL GRUNTING AND YELLING]
WOMAN:
Pillow fight!
CHANG:
Ha! Okay, I'm out.
Okay, okay. I'm dead. I'm dead.
WOMAN: Hey! Come on, get up.
ABED:
Go!
PIERCE:
I'm gonna eat you, you little--
[BOYS YELLING]
[ALL YELLING]
Okay.
PIERCE:
Get off me, you--
BOY:
I can't get mixed up!
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
MAN:
Oh, man.
Well, that's it.
I just heard from the Guinness
rep. He's not coming.
He's been fired,
in what he described
as the world's biggest mistake.
I doubt that
will make the next edition.
Anyway, it's over.
What a colossal waste
of two and a half days.
NARRATOR:
The war has no more reason
to continue,
and yet it does
between the two that began it.
ANNIE:
They just kept fighting.
Like, for hours.
Come on, let's wrap this up.
I don't wanna.
Me neither.
JEFF: Why not?
This is the last thing
we ever do together.
We can't stop.
Doesn't that kind of
solve your problem, the
realization you like each other
so much, you'd hit each other
with pillows forever?
Knowing that doesn't
feel like enough anymore.
Yeah. We're grown-ups now.
We have grown-up problems.
That's very clear.
Unless you use
those magical friendship hats
that I got for you.
We're not stupid, Jeffrey.
We know you made those
sarcastically.
Yes, yes. And I will roll
my eyes at both of you
when I put them on your heads,
because that's the way I am.
But that's not the way
you have to be.
We might be interested.
JEFF: Okay, then.
Here's your magical friendship
hat, and...
Jeff.
What?
You left the magical friendship
hats at the dean's office.
Right. Of course.
I'll go get them.
So Jeff went out
and stayed out long enough
to make them believe
he had gone to the office.
That was a nice touch. Heh.
JEFF:
Here you go.
Lucky no one grabbed them, huh?
[♪♪♪]
NARRATOR:
Britta Perry is there
to immortalize the moment
on film accidentally,
while trying to get a picture
of the light
hitting a stack of nearby
waffles.
SHIRLEY: Pierce, take that off.
PIERCE: I can't hear you.
Your cheeks are in the way.
JEFF: First entry in my journal.
Today I had to run and get
two imaginary friendship hats
from an office.
I could've walked around and
come back, but for some reason
I actually went all the way
back to where they were.
One was crumpled up.
That was Troy's.
The other was a little dusty.
That was Abed's.
I fixed them up, even though
I was the only one watching,
because I settled
on a truth today
that's always going to be true.
I would do anything
for my friends,
which I think is how everyone
in the world feels,
which finally makes me
understand war.
Guys,
I wasn't gonna show this
to anyone,
but, uh,
it's pretty profound.
I kind of nailed it.
If you want,
I can read it
in the documentary.
That is,
unless you get Tom Hanks.
NARRATOR:
We tried to get Tom Hanks,
but he's too expensive.
We used the people involved
for their own voiceover.
JEFF:
Yeah, and I nailed that too.
NARRATOR:
Why are you here,
same time as me?
JEFF:
Tight schedule.
Were you in The Cape?
NARRATOR:
No.
Wow.
I've got goose bumps.
Me too. A great story.
I was on the edge of my seat.
Wanna know what struck me
while I was watching?
You can't get quality
programming anywhere
but right here.
Was thinking that same thing.
You can't get Troy and Abed:
Pillows and Blankets.
Or these great specials like
Craig Pelton: A Year in Paris.
TROY:
From Labs to Riches:
The Annie's Boobs Story.
Or That's Enter-Chang-ment.
We know you hate
these constant pledge drives.
We know you hate them.
We don't like doing them either.
I'd rather be at home.
Taking a warm bath,
with my wife.
Oh, brother,
not this one again.
Heh, heh. But if you wanna help
Greendale Campus Television
stay on the air,
keep the lights on,
we are literally this close
to losing our fund--