We are so screwed.
How are we gonna
memorize all this?
Let's just
go over it again.
Kingdom, phylum, class...
Order, family,
genus, species.
I use a mnemonic device.
"Kevin, please come
over for gay sex."
Why wouldn't
you use "Karen"?
'Cause it's gay sex, dummy.
So use "great".
Now I can't remember
anything. Thanks!
God, why do we always
end up in this position?
For all the time
you spend here,
you'd think we wouldn't
have to cram so much.
Maybe we never
get any work done
because we have
so much fun hanging out
together.
Definitely,
maybe that's why.
Ah, the duali-Dean of man.
(GIGGLES)
I'm dressed this way
because I have good news
and bad news.
You have got to
be kidding me.
The bad news is
Professor Kane
has the flu.
The good news is
biology class is canceled.
(ALL CHEER)
After you.
What a gentleman.
Guys,
we don't have to cram
last minute anymore.
Last minute got
moved to tomorrow.
Three-hour lunch?
Three hours?
I could watch
the first half
of three movies.
Ooh, I don't have to go
to the fast food restaurant
across the street.
I can go to the fancy one
across town.
Their manager
wears a tie.
If we don't eat,
we can make-believe
an whole episode's worth
of Inspector Spacetime
in the Dreamatorium.
Word.
Yeah.
Maybe we should go
to Senor Kevin's.
Britta, didn't you want
to try that new
cage-free bean burrito?
The tortillas are made with
micro-financed flour.
Troy, you could drive.
You always like
that spiral parking ramp.
You just keep turning left,
but you end up up!
I can't go
to Senor Kevin's.
The manager and I
are enemies.
He said
Die Hard was bad.
He said  Die Hard
was bad.
I know, buddy.
Well, how about this.
This lunch is
already a runaway train,
no point in stopping it.
Troy, Britta, you go
to Senor Kevin's.
Abed promised
he'd show me how
the Dreamatorium works.
Today's the perfect day
for it.
But I want to...
Abed, don't you think
today's the perfect day
for it?
No.
Abed.
Is this a social cue?
I left my  Puttin' on the Ritz
cane in here earlier.
I know it probably
has another name,
but, um, can I be
perfectly honest
with you guys?
I think I went too far
with this one.
I have to go
to the bank today.
What am I supposed to
tell people in line?
"I had good news
and bad news"?
Come on, Craig.
Get your life together.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
I am Inspector Spacetime.
And I know that
which is unknown.
Duty-bound to
protect a universe of
innocent unremarkables,
I patrol it
in the X7 Dimensionizer
with my loyal constable,
Reggie.
This week, however,
Reggie has been forced
to go to lunch.
So I'm aboard
the much crappier
HMS Spacetime 12,
from the worst season ever,
with temporary constable,
Geneva.
Geneva, I need
the quantum spanner,
the big one.
Oi, gov'ner,
quantum spammer,
up an' at 'em, in'it?
If we can't get out
of orbital lock,
the Blorgons
may intercept.
Tut tut, m'lord.
Wouldn't give
a tuppence for
that sticky wicket.
Okay, stop simulation.
More British?
I can't do this anymore.
But the Blo-gons might
intercept...
It's Blorgons with an "r".
Blo-gon means "thank you"
in Blorgon.
Can't we play something
I know about
like hospital administration?
You're mad at me
for playing matchmaker
with Troy and Britta.
You think you're
gonna lose Troy.
I'm not petty, Annie.
I'm mad at you because
you tampered
with the fabric
of the group.
How do you know
Troy and Britta pairing up
wouldn't destroy everything?
I run the scenarios.
I examine this stuff from
every conceivable angle.
Oh, and you can do that
but I can't?
You don't have
a patent on being
a control freak, Abed.
I kind of do.
You think this is
just a room where
Troy and I play dinosaurs
versus river boat gamblers
together?
Sure, it's how I got
the construction approved,
but, much like myself,
the Dreamatorium
has higher functions.
Would you like me
to show you
how your stunt
with Troy and Britta
will play itself out?
Why not?
Execute simulation
Troy/Britta.
Render environment
Senor Kevin's.
(AS TROY)
Oh, those appetizers
were dope and legit!
(AS BRITTA)
I don't usually
support lunch
because it's unfair
to breakfast.
(AS TROY) I never
thought about meals
fighting each other.
I guess that explains
why you never
see any two of them
on the same table.
So I guess
Annie's pretty hot
to get us together.
She probably just doesn't
understand people.
Well, the sooner
the food comes,
the sooner
this will be over.
I'm afraid your food
won't be ready for
another half hour.
I'm too busy misunderstanding
the whole point of  Die Hard.
I can't wait to
get home to Abed.
So you can dart
back and forth
doing impressions
of your friends.
There's no science
at work here.
You're right.
The science is
at work in here.
This is
the Dreamatorium's engine.
My thoughts are collected
by this box
and everything I know
about my friends
is stored here.
Both are distilled by logic
and then recombined
into objective observation.
I'm able to simulate
any of the study group
and even
a half-accurate Chang
in over 7,000
unique situations.
Abed, it's cardboard tubes
and a funnel.
Well, you see it that way
because it's calibrated
to a specific level
of brain function.
Right. I'm stupid.
Not stupid,
just less able to
see what I see.
Gee, you've got it
all figured out.
(PHONE RINGS)
King of toilet paper rolls
over here.
Hey, Troy,
I'm glad you called.
Your lunch is
going well, right?
Yeah, just checking
on Abed.
Making sure he's okay.
What? He's fine.
He just implied I operate
on a lower level
of brain function,
so business as usual.
Great, um, just,
you know, make sure
he stays comfortable.
I worry about him
when I'm not around.
Well, he's fine,
he always will be.
People bend over backwards
to cater to him.
He's just extra sensitive
in the Dreamatorium.
It takes a lot out of him
to run that thing.
I don't want you to
break his brain.
Bye, Troy.
How is he?
He'll be okay.
It's so sweet how much
you care about him.
And another thing
I hate about  Die Hard,
two FBI agents
named Johnson?
I've been thinking about
our Inspector Spacetime
scenario.
It might work better
if instead of
playing Geneva,
you played Rosamund.
She was a constable
in Season Five
and she only
had three lines.
I have a better idea.
You know what would
make your scenarios
a lot more realistic?
If Troy weren't
on a date.
Why don't you take
all your thoughts
and your logic
and add one step
to the process.
What are you doing?
From now on,
before you do
or say anything,
you're gonna think
about how it affects
the people around you.
We lower functioning brains
call this "empathy".
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIMPERING)
Abed?
(SCREAMS)
Oh, my God,
I broke Abed.
Abed?
You know how
you wanted me to tell you
when you were
being scary weird
instead of cute weird?
This is scary weird.
Hello, Annie.
What was I doing
on the floor?
Were we doing it?
Are you being Jeff?
Well, I'm not
being a Kardashian.
So where are we now?
We're in
the doctor's lounge
of Greendale
Hospital School.
Hospital school?
It's a sexy
emotional school
where doctors save
lives and make love,
often simultaneously.
Our stories,
ripped from the headlines.
Our passions, unbridled.
Our cafeteria, eh...
Make love to me, Ann.
I know I'm just a surgeon
and you're a hotshot
upstart administrator,
but damn the rules,
damn the system,
damn our two foot
height disparity,
I want you.
Okay, Abed, I get it,
we have different
sensibilities.
Later.
Bye.
I'm leaving.
(STOMPS FEET)
(SIGHS)
Okay, Dr. Jeff,
can you please tell me
where I can find Abed?
I owe him an apology.
Abed?
Never heard of him.
Terrific.
I asked you a question,
doctor.
I'm a surgeon!
And I'm your administrator!
I left my wife for you
and she was pregnant!
Who do you think
inseminated her?
Now tell me
what I want to know
or God as my witness,
I'll have
your stethoscope.
Fine.
Dr. Perry might know.
Render environment
bio lab.
Look,
there's Britta and Troy
fooling around
with each other.
Look, there's Abed having
overcome his issues.
Nice try.
Dr. Barnes, Dr. Perry.
We just saved an uninsured
homeless man's life.
Using an unapproved
procedure.
Now, we're going to kiss.
This is what
you think I want?
What do you want,
administrator?
I want to talk to Abed.
There's no one here
by that name.
You're lying.
Maybe I am, so what?
I was raised on
the mean streets
of Harlem.
I'm not scared of you.
Well, be scared of this.
Sodium pentothal,
known commonly
as truth serum.
I saw Abed's name
in the hospital
school files,
I love butt stuff,
I hate spiders,
I stole a pen
from the bank,
I cried during  About a Boy...
The Soundtrack...
I don't wash my hands
before surgery.
I can see why women
find Clive Owen attractive
to the point
where I might
just as well be
attracted to him.
I use comparisons
to Hitler to win arguments
on the Internet
at the drop of a hat.
I know nothing about wine.
I'm more turned on by women
in pajamas than lingerie.
I just want to know
they feel comfortable.
I didn't get  Inception.
(SOBBING)
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
You said you saw
his name in the files.
There's so many layers.
Right, render environment
medical study room.
There's head nurse,
Shirley,
talking to tragic,
heart-wrenching
Alzheimer's patient
and Emmy-contender,
Pierce Hawthorne.
Mr. Hawthorne,
you're out of
your bed again.
'Cause I think
I'm on a train.
Oh! Oh!
Shirley, get me
the file on Abed.
Abed doesn't exist,
young lady.
He exists if I say so.
This is my hospital school.
Your hospital school,
young lady, is a simulation
being run through a filter
of other people's needs.
Abed's been filtered out
because nobody needs him.
I need him.
Well, you're not simulated.
No, but this is!
(SLAP SOUND)
Ooh!
And there's more
where that didn't
come from.
This is a private
compartment.
Jeff, get the files.
Why me?
Because you can see
the cabinets.
And I'll make love to you.
Jackpot.
There is an Abed
in this hospital school,
but he's not a doctor.
He's a patient.
Notify security!
Conductor!
Jeff, take me to Abed.
Now where is that?
Enough games,
just take me
where I wanna go.
Follow me.
Are we close?
Almost there,
although you should
probably run in place
and let the hallway
move around you.
Here we are.
Where?
Where you wanted to go.
The last night of school,
first year.
The night we kissed.
Abed wasn't there,
so whose memory is this?
Maybe it's yours.
Maybe the Dreamatorium
really works.
Or maybe
Leonard was watching
from the bushes
and told Abed about it.
I don't have cable.
Knock it off, Abed.
I'm not Abed.
You're confused
and so was I.
But not anymore.
Jeff... Abed... Stop.
I don't wanna do this.
I wanna talk to Abed.
I'm taking the file.
Oh, it says Abed
is in the recovery parlor.
Condition, never better.
You're not holding anything.
This is the file.
Abed Nadir,
psychiatric patient 1373,
control freak
with no empathy.
People bend over backwards
to cater to him.
Signed,
healthcare administrator
Annie Edison.
That's out of context.
Shh.
You've thought
of everything, Annie.
With Abed gone and
Troy and Britta together,
there's nothing standing
in the way of us.
Wait, what?
Come on.
This is you dream.
This is why you
played matchmaker.
This is what's
important to you.
You are not Jeff.
Because Jeff cares
about Abed.
And I did not push
Troy and Britta together
so this would happen.
I did it because I thought
they were cute together
and this would
have been a bonus.
And we are not here.
And I'm not staying here
because I hate
whoever you are.
You should probably
storm off in...
Oof!
In place.
Where do you
wanna go next?
I wanna be alone.
Sounds good to me.
Execute simulation,
Annie/Annie.
There. Now we're alone.
Great, so you're me now.
Why are you blowing
our magic moment
with Jeff?
It's not magic.
It's not even real.
But we love Jeff.
No, we don't.
We're just in love
with the idea
of being loved.
And if we can teach a guy
like Jeff to do it,
we'll never be unloved.
So we keep running
the same scenario
over and over
hoping for
a different result.
Running scenarios.
Careful now.
You're starting
to sound like Abed.
So...
I probably shouldn't say
things like  "Star Wars.
"Zardoz, Cougar Town,
cool, cool, cool."
Stop it.
Pop culture,
pop culture.
I'm on a TV show.
You're gonna get
in trouble.
Meta, meta.
It's Abed!
I got an Abed here!
Get him!
That's it.
I find you guilty
of being Abed.
You're under arrest!
Can I just
interject and say
I don't know what
the hell's going on?
This time
you'll never get out.
Abed?
Abed.
(ANNIE'S VOICE) Yeah.
I found you by turning
into you, how cool is that?
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
Tell me where we are
so I can pretend to see it.
We're inside a locker.
It's where I spent a lot
of time in junior high.
You think this is
where we'd put you?
You know
that's absurd, right?
Well, I'm not stupid.
You can see I've increased
the square footage.
It's a metaphorical locker.
It's a place where
people like me get put
when everyone's finally
fed up with us.
Abed, so maudlin.
If you start turning
into a vampire...
I've run the simulations,
Annie.
I don't get married,
I don't invent
a billion dollar website
that helps people have sex.
I don't make it
into Sundance,
Slamdance or dance pants.
Troy invents dance pants
in 2019.
Don't tell him,
he needs to
stumble onto it.
All right, listen.
The scenarios
you run in here
are like great
science fiction.
They're impressive
and detailed
and insightful,
but they're not
accurate for crap.
Science fiction
never has been.
Look at  2001.
Did we have
a space odyssey?
No, we got snowboarding
in the Olympics
and we over-validated
Carson Daly.
That poor guy.
Yeah, cry me a river.
My point is,
your simulations
are nothing more
than anxieties.
You're afraid
you don't fit in.
you'll be alone.
Great news.
You share that
with all of us,
so you'll never be alone
and you'll always fit in.
And, yes,
that's why I meddled
with Troy and Britta.
You caught me.
I was trying
to make life go
according to
some script.
I can't.
You can't.
We both need to get more
comfortable winging it.
At least it'll
be less work.
It would cut down
my Dreamatorium time
by 18 hours a week.
I could take up yoga.
You've got
the body type.
Now, let's get you
out of here.
I don't know how.
These fake shackles
don't have a fake key.
Isn't that what
a quantum spanner's for?
Technically, no.
But that's fine.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
So should we
get back to lunch?
I guess so.
A little more anticlimactic
than I would have
simulated it,
but whatever.
Anticlimactic?
Render environment
observo-deck,
HMS  Spacetime 12.
Inspector,
set the tachyon drive
to hyperjump.
We must get to
the other side
of this star field
before the Blorgons
intercept.
Blorgons in this sector?
Well, this mission has gone
pear-shaped, indeed.
Prepare to hyperjump
on my mark.
Bugger the dovecotes,
Inspector.
We're too late!
Blorgons!
Eradicate! Eradicate!
Our quantum blasters
are useless
against their armor.
We're as cooked
as Lord Nelson's
mutton, we are.
Not if I can help it.
I'll see you on
the other side, Inspector.
Wherever that is.
Don't you mean
"whenever that is"?
(BATTLECRY)
Take that, Blorgon scum!
You'll blo-gon me
for this later.
Ow, Annie!
Oh, oh, my God!
Abed, I'm so sorry.
No, no,
you're committing.
This is good stuff.
Thanks.
I am Abed Nadir...
And I don't know
a lot of things
everyone else knows.
I wander the universe
with my friend, Troy,
doing whatever I want.
Sometimes accidentally hurting
innocent unremarkables.
This week, however,
Troy went to lunch
and I adapted.
I now have the ability
to enter the minds
of others.
I'm hungry.
Are you hungry?
Yeah.
I'll make us
buttered noodles.
Using an elusive
new technique
known as "empathy".
So was the other
fast food place worth
the drive, Shirley?
You know,
half way there I thought,
"What am I doing?
It's the same
fast food place
in a different location.
"Have the margins
of my life become
so narrow?"
So I went to the mall
and had pizza.
I beat  The Matrix today.
Sounds like this has been
a game-changing day
for all of us.
I almost sat on my balls,
but at the last second,
I made an adjustment.
Good job!
Good work.
Good job, man.
Well, we had
a good lunch, too.
Yeah.
I spoke to the manager
about  Die Hard,
and I told him
he should be
ashamed of himself.
Thanks.
Sorry I bailed
on the Dreamatorium.
It's okay, Annie did
pretty good in a pinch.
All right,
back to cramming?
The people at the bank
loved my outfit.
And they had all kinds of
questions about it
and my answers
seemed to amuse
and...and even
liberate them a little.
A few of us went
to lunch
and I had the deepest
conversation of my life.
I gotta go,
I'm telling everybody.
Hmm, maybe after
a long, dark night,
the sun is starting
to rise on Greendale.
Maybe. Maybe not.
You never can tell
what kind of day
you're gonna have.
Okay, I didn't really
avoid sitting on them.
I sat right on them.
Oh.
Aw.
I'm sorry.
Pierce, I'm sorry.
Hurt like hell.
I saw eagles.
BOTH:
♪ Troy and Abed
in the morning ♪
Today we're joined
by Annie Edison.
Hi!
Who's gonna
show us how
to spruce up your
apartment on a budget.
So, Annie,
what inspired
this throw?
Well, I just thought
that I'd cover up
the stain
where Abed spilled Code Red
on the couch last week.
Oops. Crafty.
And you have some tips
on entertaining.
Yes, if you're
expecting company,
but you don't
have enough chairs,
you can bring out
pillows from your bedroom
and use them on the floor
for a Moroccan feel.
Ooh, a taste
of the Orient.
Ooh!
Actually, boys, I have
a little surprise for you.
Uh-oh.
While you two were out
playing blazer tag...
That's laser tag
with sport coats.
I did a little extreme
bedroom makeover!
I unbunked your beds
and got scrap fabric and...
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
It's okay, buddy.
We can put it back.
We can put it back
the way it was.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
(WHINING CONTINUES)
It's... Cut, Garrett.
Sorry!
(STUTTERING WHINE)
(HUMMING)