NARRATOR:
Greendale Community College
is represented
by two separate,
yet equally important
types of people:
The goofballs
that run around
stirring up trouble,
and the eggheads
that make a big
deal out of it.
These are their stories.
You'll be better off
without her.
She was perfect.
Warm, smart, beautiful.
I'm never gonna
find another dental
hygienist like that.
Well, you should
stop hitting on her.
Hey, she's the one
putting her hands
in my mouth.
Hey!
Over here.
Move along,
nothing to see here.
That's the first time
those words have
actually been true.
Ms. Edison,
when you called me
down here at midnight,
I expected
more than a yam.
Specifically since you said,
"There's been a murder."
Our yam was murdered.
If it's any consolation,
she got me here
on a very misleading
text message.
Jeff, technically,
you are about to be screwed
in the biology room
because our final project
has been destroyed.
All right, look,
I'm sorry for your loss.
I know you guys put
the work in, so you'll
get a passing grade.
A passing grade?
Like a C?
Why don't I just
get pregnant at
a bus station?
That was going to be
an A+ yam.
I can't give an A+
to everyone whose yam
falls off a counter.
Somebody did this to us.
In science,
we call that a hypothesis.
You find something
to back it up
and we can talk.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I was watching  Mama's Family.
What happened?
Our yam was killed.
But Professor Kane says
we can still get an A
If we figure out who did it.
He did not say that.
He basically did.
You let me handle
the nitty-gritty.
In the meantime,
I need somebody
to drum up suspects.
I can help you with that.
I watch crime shows
when I'm bored.
You boys,
canvas for witnesses,
establish a time frame
and motive
and bring me a suspect.
You've got 48 hours
before the trail runs cold,
so start with the last person
to see that yam alive.
Yes, ma'am.
Understood.
It's been a long 15 years.
TROY: Looks like
it's gonna be a late night.
How'd we manage
to pull the short straw?
It's not a short straw.
It's a hot potato.
Yeah, well,
looks pretty cold to me.
Cold? Or dead?
Survey says...
We can't both
do the zinger.
Sorry.
(PARODY OF  LAW &amp; ORDER
THEME MUSIC)
(ALL CLAMORING)
Okay, okay, 5-to-1
on the black guy.
That's offensive.
Fine, 6-to-1.
Hello, boys.
Youth! Scatter!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
slow down, Pierce.
Mind if we ask you
a couple of questions?
Sure, I always say
you guys should ask
me more questions.
Did you water
our biology yam
last night?
Of course I watered it.
It was my turn, wasn't it?
I hold up my end.
Did you hold it
or drop it?
Okay, whoa,
I had nothing
to do with that.
I...I couldn't even
get in the room.
Make up your mind, Pierce.
Did you water the yam
or weren't you there?
Okay, I lied
about watering it.
I got there too late,
the doors were
already locked.
Why were you late?
I...fell asleep
in a sunbeam.
Likely story.
Actually it is.
I used to live with him,
it's kind of adorable.
Look, why are you
looking at me for this?
It was my yam too.
You should be
talking to somebody
who would wanna hurt us.
And who's that?
Duh-doy!
Todd.
Last night,
I was home by 9:15,
helped Elly with her
geography and then
went straight to bed.
Sounds like you keep
a pretty tight schedule.
A valuable side effect
of military service.
In Iraq,
keeping a tight schedule
saved lives.
ABED: Ah,
what happened, Todd?
Cut yourself
on an extra sharp
Oscar Wilde play?
Oh, this?
It's a burn.
Home Ec class. Muffin.
What kind of muffin?
Blueberry.
Why not raisin?
That wasn't the assignment.
You can dance
all day, Todd,
but sooner or later,
the music's gonna change.
Look, even if
I wanted to hurt
your yam, I couldn't.
I went by the bio room at 8:10
to chart my yam's growth,
the door was already locked.
There's a lot of that
going around.
Oh, yeah.
It's true.
I had to take
a picture of my yam
through the door.
See?
Your yam was fine
when I left.
I transferred or "downloaded"
Todd's photograph
to this computer
and as you'll see,
with a few adjustments,
I can make the entire image...
Old West color.
I don't know.
I thought it was cool.
Britta, zoom in there.
There's a clock on the wall.
Eight plus two times five...
Ten after 8:00.
I'm gifted in other ways.
TROY: That jibes
with everyone else
we talked to.
It seems like
the classroom door
gets locked at 8:00.
Which means whoever
did the crime...
Got in there before
the doors were locked
and stayed there for hours.
I was gonna say,
"had a key".
Last year, I came in
after hours a couple
of times
to finish a pinata
for Advanced Spanish.
I had to borrow a key
from the front office.
And sign a log.
I can also help.
As a psych major,
I could...
Any student
can check out a key
as long as they're
currently taking classes
and show school ID.
The guy we're looking for
had a key to the bio room
Monday night.
Monday night?
Rings a bell.
I'll check the log.
Sorry, this place is a mess.
Is this about your yam?
I heard about that.
It's a damn shame.
Mine just bloomed yesterday.
Congratulations.
(SIGHS)
Ooh, there she is.
Monday night,
one biology room key
checked out by...
(SCATTING)
Magnitude.
So you're saying you
did check out a key,
but it was inside
your backpack
when someone
stole it off a table
in the library
while you were
using the bathroom
and you haven't
seen it since.
Pop-pop!
Perfect,
so now we gotta solve
a robbery too.
Well, whoever did it
likes to steal backpacks
off tables in the library.
Only one way to catch
a dirtbag like that.
Well, time to visit
the restroom.
(GRUNTS)
(WHISTLES)
I found that backpack.
Hey, idiot,
guess what.
We don't care
about the backpack.
Dead yam, big deal.
Order some ketchup.
That doesn't make sense.
You don't order ketchup.
It's a condiment!
ABED: Troy, Troy,
hey, walk it off!
Troy, walk it off!
Sorry, my friend,
he's a bad cop.
Yeah.
I'm a good cop.
Oh, good.
You can trust me.
Okay, well... Hey!
I'm not falling for that.
And you got nothing on me.
And I don't have to stay here,
'cause you're not cops.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
He's right.
You're not cops.
I'd say our hands are tied,
but we basically
have no hands.
But he's our man
though, right?
Well, he ain't innocent.
Look, I'll try
to keep him busy.
You guys go to the lab,
see if they figured out
how our yam met its masher.
I can, both,
see and hear you.
The yam's vascular cylinder
is completely disintegrated.
Any possibility
it happened naturally?
Sure, if the gardener's
Joseph Mengele.
Look at the root system.
This level of smushing
is consistent with
someone stepping on the yam
after it was dropped.
So whoever did this
was angry.
Hey, I just cut 'em open.
You want motive,
talk to a shrink.
What I can tell you
is that for a raw yam
to get it this bad,
you need more than gravity.
You need a boot.
(GAGS)
We have to tell
Professor Kane.
There's nothing here
to connect to Star-Burns.
He'd have to confess.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Maybe if we ask him nice,
he'll write us
a love letter too.
Well, whoever
did do this does
owe you guys a letter.
An A.
This yam was
about to bloom.
Damn.
We named the yam "Pam."
It rhymed.
Even if we could prove
that Star-Burns stole
Magnitude's key,
it's not enough.
But we know
Star-Burns did it.
Keep the change, Garrett.
You know what?
Keep the hot dog.
You're telling me
after all this,
our suspect's
gonna slip away
on the technicality
that we're not police?
Okay, look,
you don't need authority
to get a confession.
You need leverage.
Something to hold
over his head.
Like what?
He's Star-Burns.
Break into his locker.
You'll find enough dirt
to bury him.
Jeff, that's not ethical.
Oh, so now you're
finding your softness?
I say do what
you have to do.
It's too late
to get compassionate.
We only have time
to get justice.
I really shouldn't
be doing this.
And you're sure you heard
a kitten meowing in here?
Not anymore,
so hurry up.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Whoa, Nelly!
Clean up on aisle Busted.
BOTH: Why do they always...
Why do they always...
You go ahead.
Why do they always run?
There you go.
Move!
Not police business!
Hey, knock much?
Kiss me!
What?
I'll explain later.
No.
The explanation
isn't the issue.
(EXCLAIMS IN EXASPERATION)
Oh, all right, all right.
Look, I...I swiped some
beakers for the meth lab
that I'm building
in the trunk of my car.
But that's it.
I didn't kill any yam.
Tell it
to the biology professor.
Oh, now wait!
I know who did it.
I left the door open
and someone came in.
He dropped your yam.
Will you tell
our teacher who it was?
If you promise
I won't get in trouble
for stealing that
meth lab stuff.
Sure, whatever.
Fine.
Pinky swear?
It was the guy with
the weird head.
The army guy.
I heard the jar break
and then I saw him
running out of the room
holding his hand.
Looked like he cut himself.
Well, well, well.
Look at this, Abed.
He weaves baskets and lies.
What's this about?
It's about the killing
of our biology yam.
Will you please
come with us?
But I'm in the middle
of making a handle.
He wants it the hard way.
Tell him what Shirley said.
Todd Jacobson,
you have the right to do
whatever you want.
Nothing you say or do
can be used against you
by anyone,
but we'd really like it
if you came with us.
Please and thank you.
(HEAVY THUDS)
Make it quick, folks.
I have a class
in five minutes
and none of you
guys are in it.
After conducting
a full investigation,
my study group now has
definitive proof that Todd,
with malice of forethought,
smashed our yam.
That's a serious allegation.
I hope you can back it up.
We can place him
in the building Monday night.
He has a mysterious
bandage on his hand,
and we have and eyewitness
who saw Todd drop
the jar and flee.
Well, Todd, what do
you have to say?
I just wanna...
Don't answer that, soldier!
This man is
an American hero.
And who are you?
I'm Lieutenant
Colonel Archwood,
United States Army.
I had the pleasure
of commanding this
young man in Iraq.
I'm staying
on his couch
this weekend
while I'm in town
for a wedding.
I am a licensed attorney,
a veteran of two wars,
and I'd like to know
why in hell he's
being harassed.
Mr. Winger,
what is the intention here?
Simple.
When Todd smashed our yam,
he stole an A from us.
We want it back.
You mean
if he smashed the yam.
All you have is the word
of this Mr. Star-Burns,
who offers up no explanation
as to why he was at the scene.
How about it, Jeffrey?
What was Star-Burns
doing there?
We agreed to withhold
that information
as part of a pinky swear
with the witness.
(SIGHING) A pinky swear?
This is ludicrous.
This whole school
is ludicrous.
Who honors
the pinky swear
of a degenerate
over the word
of a decorated soldier?
I'm inclined to agree
with the man in uniform.
Shocker.
Jeffrey.
Tell us what Star-Burns
was doing in that classroom,
or your group
can take an F.
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
I grade my students.
Now, what Star-Face
was doing there
is irrelevant.
What matters
is what he saw.
I'm upholding
the pinky swear.
What?
Yo, man, you spent
your life in the army.
I spent mine in prison.
Two places where
a man's word is only
as good as his uniform.
Now out here,
it's supposed to be different.
And in my class,
it will be.
You two can plead
your case to the class
and let them
decide your grades.
Professor...
Thank you.
It's not a favor,
Mr. Winger.
A man's gotta have a code.
Awesome.
See you in class.
(EXHALES)
Uniform.
Oh!
Jeez.
Yeah.
Shirley did some
more digging.
Turns out Todd's yam
never even sprouted.
Goes to motive.
And Star-Burns puts Todd
in the classroom at 8:10.
Opportunity.
Add to that a cut
on the hand
and the Winger charm,
we might get an A++.
We still have
a lot of work to do.
Oh, I think you've
done enough.
Colonel Archwood
got to Star-Burns.
Threatened to involve
the real cops.
Now Star-Burns
is in the wind.
He's our only witness.
ABED: That what
you guys do in here?
You push your little papers
and you make your
little speeches,
and in the end
another dirtbag walks?
Huh? Huh?
Abed! Abed!
Abed! Walk it off!
(SCREAMS)
Walk it off!
I'm sorry about my partner.
He...he's been on edge
ever since we switched.
(SNAPS FINGERS) You.
Annie, that class
already hates us.
If we go in there
without a case,
they'll fail us.
We have proof
our yam was murdered
and now you find
your softness?
It's eat or be eaten
when that's convenient,
but when the going gets tough,
Winger gets nervous, huh?
We have no case, Annie.
It's too late
to get one, Jeff.
We only have time
to get justice.
ARCHWOOD: Tell us what
happened next, Todd.
I disarmed the IED
and returned the child
to his mother.
She offered to give me
her only possession,
a wooden chair,
but I refused.
I was only doing my duty
and we had plenty
of chairs at the base.
ARCHWOOD:
And for your valor, you were
awarded a Bronze Star.
In fact, you have
an absolutely glowing
service record.
Don't you, Private?
I do my best.
You do more
than that, soldier.
Certainly more
than this witness
who supposedly
saw you kill the yam.
A man who,
for all we know,
is a holocaust-denying,
9/11 pedophile.
(ALL GASP)
Objection.
Withdrawn.
One last question.
Did you intentionally
break into the biology room
with the express purpose
of killing
the study group's yam?
No, sir, I did not.
Thank you, soldier.
And god bless your testimony.
Your witness.
Tell me, Todd,
do you consider
yourself a hero?
Oh, no.
Of course not.
A hero doesn't call
himself a hero.
A hero gets called a hero
because of what he does.
And with your
impressive record,
not even I could
deny you the title.
Objection, she's clearly
ramping up to something.
Objection, that's not
a real objection.
Objection, I hate
the both of you.
You may proceed, Ms. Edison,
but do so with caution.
Need I remind you
this is not a courtroom?
I spent the majority
of last night
going over your records
with Mr. Winger,
scouring them for
the slightest mistake,
the tiniest slip up.
And I gotta tell you, Todd.
Couldn't find a thing.
Not one little smudge.
Except, of course,
for one pesky yam
that just wouldn't grow.
That had to weigh
on your soul,
didn't it, Todd?
Maybe a little.
A little?
A big orange splotch
on your perfect record?
I bet that pissed you
right off, didn't it?
Is that why
you hit your wife?
Withdrawn.
Is that why you drink
and pop pills? Withdrawn.
Are you a virgin?
Withdrawn.
Did you...
kill our yam to settle
the score, huh?
Did stomping on its roots
make you feel like a big man?
No, it didn't.
I mean, I didn't...
Todd, zip it.
No, you zip it,
Uncle Knobby.
I'm not fighting
your wars anymore.
(ALL MURMURING)
ANNIE: Listen to me, Todd.
I know how scary
a failing grade can be,
but this one dead yam
won't tarnish your record.
What will tarnish it
is lying to your class,
to your teacher,
and to me.
The American citizen
you've sworn to protect.
Come on, Todd.
Stop disappointing me.
Defuse the IED
of dishonesty.
It was an accident.
(ALL GASP)
I just wanted
to look at your yam,
but when I picked up the jar,
it burnt me and I dropped it.
Booyah!
(LAUGHS)
That's how it's done!
(SCATTING)
Todd...
ANNIE: Woo-hoo!
I'm telling your mother.
That's right.
Always have
an exit strategy.
(TODD CRIES)
(KANE BANGS TAPE DISPENSER)
I think I've heard enough.
Professor Kane,
may we have a sidebar
in your office?
(SIGHS)
I want a mistrial.
Just give us a C,
give Todd a C.
Excuse me?
What?
Can we take a sidebar
in this sidebar?
Jeff, we're about
to get our A.
Todd didn't do it.
Um, he just confessed, dummy.
He said the jar burned him?
It doesn't make any sense.
People don't
half-confess to crimes.
Look, when we started this,
you were after the truth.
And then I convinced you
it was more important to win.
Don't be like me.
A man's got to have a code.
I can only assume there is
a female equivalent to that.
A codette or something.
But...
It's not worth
getting an A
if an innocent man
might get an F.
Okay, I heard all of that
and I accept.
(KANE BANGS TAPE DISPENSER)
All right.
After speaking
to the wronged parties,
I've decided to...
Uh, if it pleases
the bio class,
I have closing arguments.
Of course you do.
Why was it so hard
for all of us to grow a yam?
It's just a stupid yam
in a stupid jar.
We're all fully-grown
adults failing
a kindergarten project.
Can I object?
I'll allow it.
Sustained.
And all this time
we assumed
our yam was targeted,
that someone had stomped
its roots maliciously.
But what if...
What if our yam's roots
were dead before
they hit the ground?
(SPLAT)
Hey, that's mine!
JEFF: Look at it.
Everyone look.
Smushed without
being stepped on.
(SPLAT)
Because it didn't
have to be stepped on.
Because it was boiled.
(SPLAT)
Someone has been
pouring boiling water
into our jars at night.
No one noticed
because the water
cooled off by morning.
Boiling water
is the icicle stabbing
of yam-killing.
(ALL GASP)
Ooh, but that didn't...
Hmm.
This yam isn't boiled.
Vicki?
I don't...
I didn't do it, I swear!
I boiled the yams.
(ALL GASP)
Vicki's yam never sprouted
and I didn't want her to fail,
so I threw off
the grading curve
so she wouldn't have
to go to summer school
and we can finally have
sex in my parents' cabin.
God forgive me,
I did it for love!
(CRIES)
KANE: Holy crap.
We are definitely
dissecting pine cones
next year.
Neil has agreed
to retake biology
over the summer
and his status
as keymaster
has been revoked.
After all the politics
and procedure,
in the end,
the case really
was about biology.
Told you it was
an important subject.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
I understand.
Star-Burns got rear-ended
and the meth lab
in his trunk exploded.
He's dead.
Abed?
Yeah?
Why don't we have
bunk bed conversations?
I don't know.
We're best friends,
we share a bunk bed.
Seems like we should be
having them all the time.
You start.
Okay. Why do you think
they call them "bunk beds"?
Where's the word "bunk"
come from?
I don't know.
I think it comes
from the word "bunker."
So when is your apartment
done being fumigated?
Oh, it was done
about a week ago.
Then why are
you still here?
I brought you
some warm milk.
Oh.
There you go.
♪ Troy and Abed
off to Dreamland
♪ Catching the train
to Sleepytown
♪ And when they wake up
♪ The Dean'll be here
♪ Staring at you ♪
Sweet deans.
(GIGGLES)
That's nice...
I guess.