Look at us,
still together as a group,
even, what, two months
after being kicked out
of you know where.
Yeah, good thing
I came up with this idea
for potluck dinners.
Pierce, all you said was,
"I'm hungry."
All Henry Ford said was,
"I need a ride."
Troy, is that a casserole?
It's Bagel Bites
in a deconstructed
hot pocket reduction
with a Doritos glaze.
I just really want
to make my food,
you know.
Did anybody
bring anything
that isn't poison?
I need to eat
natural, organic foods,
or I'm never gonna get rid
of this hangover.
Jeff, what'd you bring?
Pack of Life Savers.
(CLANK)
(SHRIEKS)
Sorry.
Dead battery.
Where's Abed?
Have you seen Abed?
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
He's probably out getting
something really cool
for the dinner.
See? Cool. Abed brought
delicious police.
Abed,
what happened?
Found your friend going
through the dumpster
outside the administration
building in Greendale again.
This cadet could
use a lesson in
intergalactic protocol.
It's okay, Officer.
He's just playing
a character from TV.
Oh, yes, I'm very familiar
with Inspector Spacetime.
You think a guy
becomes a cop
because his prom night
was a dream?
If this were Comic-Con,
I'd take a bullet
for that kid.
But, here in the real world,
trespassing is a crime.
We're sorry, Officer.
Our friend has been
having a hard time
adjusting to
being expelled
from Greendale.
It won't happen again.
That's for sure.
I talked to
your former dean.
I recommended
he press charges.
He said he'd hold off
on the condition
that you set
an appointment
with this guy.
He's offering to
foot the bill for
the consultation himself.
It's the number
for a psychiatrist.
What? No.
Abed's not crazy.
Where does
the dean get off?
He's not the real dean.
He's been replaced
by an identical life-form
for some nefarious purpose.
Reggie,
to the Time Booth.
We haven't much...
Space.
I'll be right there,
Inspector.
Hey, before I go,
you really shouldn't
be using this
to prop open
your building's door.
This is
an antique fire brick.
I'd say pre-civil war.
Note the uneven orange hue
and the embossment
on the back.
What a nifty little piece
of Americana.
You could get 50,
60 bucks for it
from the right collector.
I watch a lot
of  Antiques Roadshow.
Oh.
Anyway, walk to your cars
in pairs tonight.
Rape's up 8%.
(DOOR SHUTS)
$60?
Hello? Rich people,
Troy's joining you.
Yes, I'll hold.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
Abed.
I'm Dr. Heidi.
We're going to have
a little chat tonight,
you and I.
How does that sound?
I don't need therapy.
Well, that's a perfectly
normal response.
I concur with
Dr. Heidi's diagnosis.
I haven't diagnosed
anything yet.
Psych major.
Got your back, brah.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
I have to say,
I didn't expect
to see so many of you.
Abed won't go to any kind
of doctor on his own.
We caught him last year
trying to remove
his own tonsils.
Well, why don't you let me
take it from here?
You have to understand
about Abed.
He's usually, you know,
adorable weird,
like Mork from Ork,
but, since we got expelled,
he's been creepy weird,
like present-day
Robin Williams.
I'm not crazy.
Well, Abed,
I don't deal in crazy.
I deal in health.
Hmm.
So how long has Abed needed
a crazy amount of help?
All of this behavior started
after you were expelled?
There may have been
a ramp-up.
(MOANING)
TROY: It's okay, buddy.
Just a few more minutes,
and we're good
until spring, okay?
But it doesn't
make any sense.
Think of it this way.
We get the hour back
later in the year.
Yeah.
(SHRIEKS)
I rented  Tower Heist
last night,
and I won't
spoil the ending,
but let me tell you,
it was quite
the hilarious thrill ride.
That Brett Ratner,
he's a master at
comedic action-adventure.
Mmm.
A master at storytelling.
He's just a master
at making movies
in general.
I'm gonna say it.
He's the new Spielberg.
(THUD)
Oh!
I have to go.
Excuse me.
Okay.
You're a bad person.
ABED: Time enough at last
to eat a sandwich.
Though even he knew
that this sandwich
was nearer
his last sandwich
than his first.
Abed, I'm trying to eat.
He said, oldly,
his brittle bones straining
to support the weight
of his wrinkly skin.
Stop narrating me.
He shouted to no one,
just a man alone in time
with nothing
but the cold squishiness
of tuna salad
to comfort him.
I take it back.
I don't want
to be in your novel.
Pierce Hawthorne
had nearly lost
his grip on reality.
Lately, he'd begun to think
he was in a novel.
And action.
Abed, what the hell
are you doing?
Cut. We got it.
One more for safety.
Abed, it's 4:30
in the morning,
and you're in my bedroom.
Use that. Okay.
And action.
But that's almost completely
nearly all of it.
If Abed is as sick
as you all say,
then I have no...
Wait a minute.
Nobody in this room
gets to define sick.
I do.
I'm a psychiatrist.
Any kind of doctor
can really.
Really?
Yes.
Well, if Abed's sick,
then we're all sick.
ALL: Yeah.
You can't determine
a person's sanity from
a few amusing stories.
Exactly.
That's right.
I mean, if anything,
Abed's more sane
than any of us.
ALL: Yeah.
Well.
I mean, he's certainly
the craziest one of us,
but, you know,
we're all kind of
crazy-town banana pants.
Talk to me about
Look, we're just saying
it's been a crazy year
for everybody.
Who among us hasn't
had the odd banana
in his or her pants, right?
I have.
(LAUGHTER)
How long
does peyote last?
Just asking for a friend.
♪ Troy and Abed and Annie
in the morning ♪
(DOOR OPENS)
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Nothing my ass.
What are all these cameras
doing here?
(RADIO PLAYING MUSIC)
Here, take my coat.
Oh.
Thank you.
That's so sweet.
Just don't eat anything
or drink anything,
and no sweating
or bending at the elbows,
and no chairs
with backrests,
and if you take it off,
wooden hangers only.
You're probably
warm now, right?
Good news, guys.
I spent all my money.
Troy, you can't
bring that in here.
Yes, I can.
It's all-terrain, dummy.
I made a plate of cookies
for the study group,
but my boys ate them,
so since they took
something of yours,
you all get something
of theirs.
Elijah loves this,
Britta.
There you go, Jeff.
There you go, Troy.
Karate championship,
second place!
Now I'll be unstoppable.
Oy-ay!
(SCREAMS)
So you see
what you call insanity
we call solidarity.
(HISSES)
(GASPS) I'm sorry.
We just finished
telling him about it,
and you grab it
and squeeze it?
I said I was sorry.
Uh-huh. And so as a group,
do you always indulge Abed
in these little
misadventures?
Take that back.
Our adventures
are very manly.
I have to say
there's more important
to mental health
than a support system.
And assuming that
this group is, for Abed,
said support system,
I think
I've heard everything
I need to hear
in order
to make a decision.
I think that Abed
should be committed.
You mean committed
to his character work,
right?
Because he already is.
Abed, show him
your Don Draper.
Cigarettes.
(LAUGHTER)
No, I mean an institution.
You mean like marriage?
I mean
a mental institution.
Ah. So do I.
Will someone
please help me
lighten the mood?
(SOBBING) Please,
Mr. Dr. Psychiatrist, sir,
please don't
send my best friend
to crazy people jail.
Relax.
He doesn't have the right.
Abed's not dangerous.
Yeah,
he's just unique,
like a snowflake
who gets
bent out of shape
when you mix up  Star Wars
and  Space Treks.
Or a serial killer's
signature.
I'm a psych major.
His continued obsession with
Greendale Community College
suggests the potential
for escalation.
And, frankly, these stories
you've been telling me
are very troubling.
You're troubled?
I don't remember any
of those things happening.
Since when do these three
live together?
Look, Abed's obsession
with Greendale
doesn't make him crazy.
If you had gone
to school there,
you'd be obsessed
with it too.
It was a messed-up place.
We had lockers.
Yeah.
We're survivors.
My name is
Pwofussa Wobinswin.
Who's weady to wearn?
Dean, this is not the way
to agree on parking
for the job fair!
It's inhumane.
You have a better idea,
Britta?
Yes.
Thousands of them.
Vicki to queen 3.
Neigh.
(EXHALES)
That's all for today.
Read chapter four.
Okay, we're
just gonna ignore that.
(FLUSHING)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
WOMAN 1: Bananas?
Yes.
WOMAN 2: Toast?
MAN: Bubble gum?
Yes.
WOMAN 3: Pancakes?
WOMAN 4: Fries?
Get out.
There's one every year.
I will not tolerate clowning.
WOMAN 5: Car keys?
Yes.
Okay, last bathroom break.
We've got to cram for...
Excuse me, sir,
can we get to our...
(BARKS)
(SCREAMING)
Slow your bones, Rufus.
We got a long road
tomorrow.
Welcome...
To Ladders.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Interesting.
Eh.
Just wanted to see
if we got the same thing.
It sounds as though
this Greendale had
quite an effect on all of you.
You should all definitely
stop dwelling on it
if you want to be healthy.
Well, come on,
it wasn't all bad.
I was there
longer than anybody,
and I'm fine.
How are you?
Why do you ask?
3:30.
(CHUCKLES) Uh-oh.
What Pierce was saying
before he started
sundowning is true.
We can't just pass
the crazy buck
to Greendale.
It could be
a good place too.
That really doesn't matter.
Yeah, we have a lot
of memories
of Greendale
being in our corner.
Dean-a-ling.
I just wanted to drop by
and tell you we ought
to be hot-stepping it out
to the parking lot
in a brisk,
but orderly fashion.
Is there a fire drill?
No, sir,
there's an actual fire.
I wanted you guys
to be the first to know
before I tell everyone else.
I know. It's not right
to play favorites,
but it is no more right
to sit on your feelings,
and I don't know
what I'd do
without you guys.
Whoa. Okay.
Fire, fire!
There's a fire!
Darcy,
you've got a cold.
I feel fine.
You're sick. Go home!
Get out of here.
Get out of here!
I can't believe we got here
too late for pizza.
Worst pizza day ever.
Oh, darn it.
What am I gonna do
with all this garbage?
Psst, it's me,
the dean.
I pulled
the last six pieces
of pizza for you.
ALL: Oh.
Back to garbage detail.
PELTON OVER PA:
We have a few students
with birthdays today,
but, hey,
why single them out?
What about the students
who aren't celebrating
anything at all?
Are they any less special?
(CLEARS THROAT)
♪ Troy and Jeffrey
♪ And Annie and Britta
♪ And Shirley and Pierce
♪ And Abed and Jeffrey
♪ Just a few of
the most special students
in the world ♪
(GUNFIRE)
Damn it.
Out of slugs.
Next time,
I'll put you square,
you pickle-sucking
McGillycuddy.
(GASPING)
Why did you
save me, Dean?
I know how important
paintball is to you, Abed.
I wanted you to win.
It's not important anymore.
I get it now.
It just feels forced.
You just enjoy
your prize.
Free tickets to...
(COUGHS)
To see  Chicago
at the Greendale
Civic Center...
(COUGHING)
With George Wendt and...
Stefanie Powers.
Lame!
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Okay. That was great,
but you really didn't need
to go into it.
You know
what occurs to me?
What all those
great Greendale memories
have in common?
I was barely in them?
They were all
about Dean Pelton.
That's what I've been trying
to make you guys understand
for the last two months.
I keep telling you,
we weren't expelled
by the real dean.
It couldn't have been him.
He loved us.
Maybe we've been so concerned
with moving past Greendale,
we've been living
in denial.
It's true.
I mean, let's face it.
We weren't driven crazy
by Greendale.
And Abed's not the crazy one
for obsessing about it.
Abed, we're sorry.
We haven't been
supporting you,
and we haven't been honest
with ourselves.
Dr. Heidi,
something weird is going on
with that school.
Abed doesn't
need to be here.
We need to be there.
But there is no there.
That's the problem.
That's why we have
to go back.
No, you can't go back
to Greendale.
Why? Because
it isn't healthy?
'Cause it doesn't exist.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(GASPS)
I parked by a meter.
Any of y'all park
by a meter?
Wait, what?
(THUNDER CRASHES)
What do you mean,
Greendale doesn't exist?
Well, there is a place
called Greendale,
and you all spent
three years there,
but it was
not a community college.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
These memories
that you people
have been sharing
are a shared psychosis.
You were patients
there together,
you were released together,
and I am alarmed to see
that you are now
relapsing together.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
This is not real.
You're lying.
Search your mind
for the real memories.
Try to look past the trauma
you've been blocking out.
What trauma?
You all came
to this community college
after your lives
had fractured.
Pill addiction,
failed legal career,
broken marriage,
lost scholarship,
old...
Enough! I don't want
to hear mine.
And if we were going
to fabricate a delusion,
why would we fabricate
a community college?
Ah, yes, this fantastical
community college
where everything that happens
is unbelievably ridiculous
and it all revolves
around you as a group.
The same reason anyone
plunges into psychosis,
Miss Perry.
It was a mentally-compatible
alternative to
your grim reality.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Can you believe the secret
trampoline we found?
I know.
It's so great.
(GIGGLES)
(BOTH IMITATING GUNFIRE)
For Greendale!
Charge!
Come on, Leonard.
Yow!
Ooh!
BOTH:
♪ Baby Boomer Santa
♪ Thank you for everything
♪ You're welcome,
you're welcome
♪ For everything
in the world
Terry, stop it.
♪ You're welcome, hey ♪
Let's do a clip show.
Bottle episode.
Don't forget
the clip show.
Harrison Ford.
Remember when
we went camping?
ALL: Yes.
Remember when we painted
the nursery?
ALL: Yes.
Remember when we
remembered going camping
while we were in the nursery?
(MOANS)
I'm a millionaire,
I'm an inventor,
I'm a legend,
and I had sex
with Eartha Kitt.
It's sad.
Should we increase
their lithium?
Not yet.
I want to see what happens
if we confiscate
one of their pens.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
It's not possible.
Mmm. You say
you started as
a Spanish study group.
Do any of you
speak Spanish?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
And you've
attended Greendale
for three years,
but don't community colleges
end after two?
Everyone's always
saying that.
The average community
college student
attends school
five to seven years.
Many offer
four-year degrees.
In your mind, they do.
In your mind.
And you shared
this delusion
with each other,
like that time
all those people got
into swing dance music
back in the '90s.
And then
you were released,
probably because
your insurance ran out.
But the official story
is that you're now fit to
live within society again.
You just have to
accept the truth.
Wait.
Give me a break.
That made no sense.
Yeah, it's me.
No, I think
they bought it.
I had to do a little riffing
at the end,
but I was
pretty convincing.
Well, if it looks
like I'm sneaking
out the window,
it's just a symptom
of your deepening
psychosis.
Don't hurt me.
Greendale doesn't exist?
How long did you
think we'd buy that?
I'm literally carrying
a Greendale backpack.
I have, like, 1,000 pictures
of the campus on my phone.
I have children
I see every day.
I have definitely
not been locked up.
Get him.
Why would you lie
to make us think
we were crazy?
Because, Ms. Edison,
Greendale is purgatory,
and I am the devil.
PIERCE: What?
I knew it.
Stop letting him
make you realize stuff.
These aren't
even good lies.
All right, fine,
I had to come up
with something.
You were getting too close.
Close to what?
To the truth.
The Indian kid was right.
He's Arabic.
Also Polish.
Whatever.
I'm a fake psychiatrist,
not a fake ethnologist.
The point is your dean
was kidnapped by Ben Chang
and replaced with a double.
I was hired
to keep you
off the scent.
Chang kidnapped the dean?
Even for him,
that's insane.
Is it?
Think about it.
(HUMS)
Whoo!
I said hot damn!
Chang?
What are you doing?
I'm predicting
future crimes.
(SNEEZES)
Now I'm sick.
See, you said
that would happen.
You are a pre-cog!
(SCREAMS)
Again.
You're weak.
Uh, guys,
while we were
remembering
Chang is crazy,
the fake doctor
sneaked away.
Oh, crap!
What?
There goes our only chance
of clearing our names.
You guys,
forget about us.
The dean has
been kidnapped.
He's out there somewhere,
alone and cold
and most likely
trying to cobble together
a sexy Patty Hearst costume.
Britta's right.
Wait, what?
We need to rescue the dean.
We need to get back
to that school.
And we definitely
never need to do
another paintball.
SHIRLEY: Yeah.
See, therapy does work.
We're cured.
Aw. Aw.
Sounds like
the study group
has gotten wise
to Operation Doppel-deaner.
It's time for Phase Two.
What's Phase Two?
Hey, I'm making up
the same plan you are.
Pitches, pitches, pitches.
Ah, thank you, Megan.
BOTH:
♪ Troy and Abed
in the morning ♪
Nights.
Welcome back,
all you night owls.
Troy,
why don't we open up
the phone lines?
Talk to us, lonely hearts.
We got Jeff W. calling.
JEFF:
Hello?
Hey, Jeff,
what's your question?
Who is this?
Great question.
We're us.
You guys,
it's 3:00 in the morning.
I'm trying to sleep.
I'm sorry to
hear that, Jeff.
Why don't you stay
on the line and we'll
get your information.
Yeah, we'll get you
the help you need.
Our next caller's Annie E.
What's on your mind
tonight, Annie?
ANNIE:
Hey, guys, long time,
first time,
love the show.
Aw, appreciate ya.
How can we help?
(THUMPING ON DOOR)
ANNIE: (SCREAMING)
You can shut up
and go to sleep.
Well, Jacks and Jills,
that's about all the time
we have tonight.
Yeah, until next time,
may your dreams be sweet
and your nightmares
be "spooky monster" scary
and not "grandma died" scary.
BOTH:
♪ Troy and Abed
in the morning ♪
Nights.