Pierce, you made us all
drive out to a warehouse
in the middle of nowhere.
You could at least
tell us why.
Hey, I know
as much as you.
I got a letter
from the executor
of my father's estate.
It said to come out here
with my seven closest friends.
You brought six.
Well, who else
was he gonna bring?
LeVar Burton was a maybe.
Mr. Hawthorne.
(ALL GASP)
I apologize.
PIERCE: Gilbert.
Even from the grave,
my father's got you
by the short and curly
salt and pepperies.
My name is Gilbert Lawson.
I was Cornelius Hawthorne's
assistant for over 30 years,
and before that,
I was just the teenager
who read the Bible to him
in the bath.
Ew.
All right, all right.
It's inheritance time.
How 'bout that check,
soul brother?
Your father did
leave you something,
but it's more of
an activity.
Thank you for keeping it
as creepy as possible.
This looks like
a multi-player
gaming interface.
I've heard enough.
Oh, that diabolical
old fossil face.
I asked him for money
to invest in video games
back in 1979.
Cornelius spent
over 30 years developing
a video game for you.
It was his dying wish
that you and seven
of your closest friends
would play it.
LeVar Burton was a maybe.
So, please,
choose a seat.
Cool.
JEFF: So a 100-year-old man
designed a 30-year-old
video game?
This I've got to see.
GILBERT: Once you're seated
behind your computers,
a photograph of you
will be taken
and an avatar will be made
from your likeness.
I didn't bring
my likeness.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
GILBERT: Don't smile.
All right, everyone,
let's begin.
(TYPING)
(8-BIT VERSION OF
AT LEAST IT WAS HERE PLAYING)
(WHIZZING)
Nice!
Cool.
Old school.
Cool, cool, cool.
Which one is me?
I assume nothing because
I'm not racist.
Aww! We're adorable!
Why did this thing
take photos
if it was going to
completely fabricate
random body shapes?
That's what I'm saying!
My hair looks good, though.
Orange button is jump.
(BOINGING)
Whee!
Which guy am I?
There's a door here.
(DOOR CLICKS)
Peace. Love.
What's that?
I think it's a hippie.
Peace. Love.
Aww!
Annie, stop "awing"
Everything.
Don't be jaded.
He's saying "peace."
Hello.
Sex.
Did he say "sex"?
Drugs. Sex.
Oh, my God.
Hold on, I'm coming.
Oh! Oh! Ow! Ow!
Darn! Shoot!
Dang it. Um...
Jeff, you just
murdered Annie.
Well, better than
doing nothing!
I'm not sure
that's the case.
That's debatable.
You guys, help me.
The way you
helped Annie?
Sex.
Before we engage,
we should hang back and
study their tactics.
What?
Group sex.
Oh, my God!
Oh, cool, I'm alive.
Pierce?
This game
makes no sense.
What happened
to you?
I don't want to
talk about it.
Pierce, point
the joystick right.
So I'm supposed to
just guess that?
Where are
the instructions?
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
Take that!
Yeah, we rule!
Oh, you guys
are alive.
You re-spawn
in the study room
when you die.
Here, I'll show you.
Hey!
Jeffrey!
Shame on you!
"Hang back and study
their tactics"?
Let him get it
out of his system.
Ah, forget it.
Let's just keep moving.
(DINGING)
(ELECTRONIC PULSE)
Now what?
MALE VOICE:
Welcome to Hawkthorne.
That's dad's voice.
Dad?
(ELECTRONIC WHOOSH)
Piercinald, in 1980,
you said that video games,
not moist towelettes,
were the business
of the future.
Today, moist towelettes are
stocked in every supermarket,
while arcade after arcade
closes.
He's got a point.
Nevertheless,
I designed this game
to be played
upon my death
by you and whatever
cabal of fruits,
junkies, and sluts
you call your friends.
Her name is Britta.
Only one player can win.
The first to reach my throne
inside Castle Hawkthorne.
Their reward, Pierce,
will be your inheritance.
What?
His inheritance?
So you see, Pierce,
turns out you were right.
Video games are important.
(LAUGHS)
Worst son ever!
Well, great.
How do I fight you guys?
Which button fights?
Pierce, stop.
Pierce, relax.
Pierce, stay in the game,
stay in the game.
Pierce, calm down.
Nobody's gonna
fight you.
Why not?
Because when you're
friends with someone
for three years,
it's weird to steal
their family's money.
And there wouldn't
be a lot of sport
in beating you.
Look at yourself.
Yeah, he's right.
You're playing
the game wrong.
(ALL SCREAM)
Why is Harry Belafonte
in here?
It's Gilbert.
You're not supposed to
cooperate,
you're supposed to compete.
Thanks for the advice,
but I think we can choose
how we want to play.
I suppose we can.
Is he being ominous?
Why are you
being ominous?
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPS)
Whoa.
We can pick stuff up?
This game is more complex
than you can imagine.
And aside from
its programmers,
who have all been
deported back to China,
I'm the one who knows
how it works.
(SCREAMING
AND OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
JEFF: Run, run!
ABED:
He's gonna throw a knife!
Go! He's gonna
throw a knife!
Jump! Jump!
(SCREAMING AND YELLING)
Wah!
(DESCENDING ELECTRONIC TONE)
(FAST-PACED MUSIC)
Wait! What are you...?
(BEEPS)
He's a psychopath!
He's suffo...
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
(DESCENDING TONE)
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
Hey, look, buddy,
I know it must have sucked
being Colonel Sanders'
manservant and all,
but Pierce is technically
our friend,
and we're not gonna
watch you screw him over.
Perhaps you should be
asking yourselves
how you intend to stop me.
How about if we
come over there and
kick your ass?
Go get him, Troy.
GILBERT: Be my guest.
But 30 seconds after you
leave your chairs,
the weight sensors
will recognize it
as an automatic forfeit.
Weight sensors?
(WHIZZING)
That's it.
Let's get that jag!
Yeah!
Get him!
ANNIE:
Kick that hippie's ass!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Let's go!
Move, move, move!
I think he left a note.
What?
"After you've squandered
the last of your savings,
"I'll watch you writhe,
penniless, in the gutter,
"through a telescope
in the penthouse office
of Hawthorne tower."
(MUSICAL TONES)
You can leave notes.
This game is incredible.
Pierce?
(ELECTRONIC PULSE)
No, Pierce!
Please, no!
We need you!
Just let me die.
Pierce, so Gilbert
knows a couple tricks.
Big deal.
We outnumber him.
And most importantly,
while he's fighting
for greed,
we're fighting
for friendship,
which means
we can't lose, okay?
Okay.
Okay!
(DESCENDING TONE)
I guess
there's no hug button.
Everybody keep
Pierce protected.
We have to get him to
the throne of Hawkthorne
before Gilbert.
And don't forget,
when you die,
you go all the way back
to the study room.
So...don't die.
Good pep talk, Jeff.
Yeah,
I used to love dying,
but that speech really
turned me around.
Whatever.
(PEACEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
What's that?
Kill it!
It's a girl milking a cow,
Pierce.
I'll check it out.
I owe Jeff that.
I wasn't gonna say it.
(SPEAKING)
PIERCE: Lesbian.
Shh!
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
(BEEPS)
(SPEAKING)
Cool.
(BEEP)
(SPEAKING)
I'm picking up on
some hidden symbolism.
Right,
"white crystal."
You think dad
was into meth?
You can usually
get supplies
in a town like this.
Man, why can't my mom
be here?
She always said
my video game knowledge
would come in handy.
I never believed her.
Everybody split up
and take a hut.
Our only chance of
beating Gilbert is
to cover more ground.
(BEEPS)
I have information
on the following topics.
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
(BEEPS)
Holy crap.
Where have you been
my whole life?
(HAMMERING TONES)
I buy and sell
weapons and armor.
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
Cool.
We need weapons.
(BEEPS)
Well, what's free?
Can we have a torch?
Thief! Thief!
Annie, put it back.
Sorry. Sorry.
Arr! Arr!
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Oh, oh! Oh, no!
Oh, my God.
What are you doing?
It was an accident!
Arrr!
He's dying!
Arrrrrr!
All right, hold on,
hold on!
Arrr! Arrr!
Now what are you doing?
He was suffering!
Yeah, from axe wounds!
Well, if this isn't
worth any points,
what is?
You're asking me?
I'm still looking for
a pong paddle.
(SPEAKING)
Oh, now we're talking.
Check the desk.
I'll check the dresser.
How do I straighten
that painting?
JEFF: You can't.
Stop playing like a girl.
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
(BEEP)
Stop playing
like a girl?
Here's the thing
about women, Jeff.
We don't hack and slash
our way through life
because we're
one with life.
Help me hide the body.
Oh, my Lord.
Shirley,
these things happen
in video games.
They do?
Yes.
We can't get hung up
on real world morality.
We need to
survive and win.
(SPEAKING)
Aah! Help!
Oh, crap!
Guard the door.
What?
(BEEPS)
Shirley!
No witnesses!
Grab everything
you can carry.
I'll check upstairs
for any more family.
Don't give me that look.
These are your loose ends.
I'm just tying 'em up.
This is so cool.
Where are
your clothes?
Pierce taught me poker.
I'm not good at it.
You still talking
to this girl?
Yeah, she only has
three moves
that you activate
with basic
patterns of stimulus.
I've never felt
this way before.
Abed, don't get weird.
Oh, I won't.
She's not ready
for anything serious,
but she wants me
to meet her family.
My father is
the blacksmith.
Her father's
a blacksmith.
Hello!
Everybody go shopping?
That's all we did.
Is that hut on fire?
Oh, my.
What an unexplained
tragedy.
Don't we look comfy
at a cauldron.
Check it out.
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
(BEEPS)
Ooh, see, I'll put
all of this in here,
and then that,
and then I'll hit this.
(ELECTRONIC PULSES)
What is it?
I assume, like,
a strength potion.
Then I assume
it's poison.
You're just jealous
because we found a world
where I know
what I'm doing.
This place is 20 cat turds
and a Pixies poster
from being your apartment.
(CRYING)
What's with
the St. Pauli girl?
Hilda's parents
lived there.
Now she has no family.
She'll be forced to marry
a male villager
or take her chances
in the wilderness.
What kind of game
is this?
Oh, crap, it's Gilbert.
Well, well, well.
Looks like someone's
one step behind.
Yeah, if you're
looking for equipment,
tough luck.
The store was lost
in a freak accident.
I hardly need equipment,
young lady.
While you were shopping,
I gained enough levels
to do this.
SHIRLEY: Uh-huh,
come on and bring it!
He's shooting lightning
and I'm naked!
Get behind us!
We have armor!
(SCREAMS)
Oh, great! Gilbert!
(GRUNTS)
Oh, great!
Evil Jedi lightning Gilbert!
(GROANS)
Oh!
Britta, drink that
super strength potion
you made.
(GASPS)
Oh, right, right,
right, right.
Hurry up, Britta!
I'm trying, I'm trying!
(SCREAMS)
Damn it, I thought we
could count on Britta
to not screw up drinking.
This'll be fun.
(ELECTRONIC PULSES)
What the hell?
Here's hoping
we can count on her
to screw up making potions.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMS)
(DESCENDING TONE)
(ALL CHEERING)
Unbelievable.
Jeff bet all our lives
on Britta and won,
and I lost my pants
to a pair of nines.
(WHIZ)
(SIGHS)
Very well.
Let's play.
(TYPING)
Abed, are you sure
about this?
Yeah. It just feels like
the right thing to do.
Hey, I made it back.
You guys never died.
How did you beat Gilbert?
Oh, you know.
Teamwork.
We were headed
for the black caves
to find
the white crystal.
We were just saying
goodbye to Abed.
I'm gonna stay here
in the village with Hilda
and help her
rebuild her life.
Abed, she's a program.
People have said
similar things about me.
Uh-oh. He's playing
the rain man card.
Let's bounce.
I've got an inheritance
to win.
(GAMING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SWOOPING TONE)
BRITTA:
Offensive. Called it.
JEFF: Shut up, Britta.
(SWOOPING TONE)
PIERCE: You did great
in there, Jeff.
Shut up, Pierce.
(BEEP)
(MUSICAL TONES)
TROY: Okay, duck.
Stay ducked.
Okay, unduck.
Okay, now jump.
I think
we're almost there.
Thank God.
This cave is the worst.
I know, I don't know
what's more offensive...
The actual racism
or the insulting notion
that it might somehow
rub off on us.
(TURKEY GOBBLING)
Look out! Jive turkeys!
Kill them before
they start multiplying!
(ALL YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
Yeah, suck on this!
Take that, jive turkey!
(GROANS)
(TURKEY GOBBLING)
(SWOOPING TONE)
All right!
The white crystal!
(ALL CHEERING)
Get it!
I'll take it.
I've earned it
by having friends.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
This is it.
(ALL CHEERING)
It certainly is.
No, man!
You again?
Now I'll have
that crystal.
I think you'll
have this.
(ZAPPING)
Whoops.
Arrows!
(DINGING)
(ELECTRONIC PULSES)
What? Come on!
(BEEPS)
Where'd you get
all that stuff?
You've only been alive
for an hour.
(SWOOPING TONE)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ELECTRONIC TONES)
BRITTA:
Well, that was not fair.
What the hell, Gilbert?
You're cheating,
which I have
no problem with,
but you're getting caught,
and that's not cool!
Yeah, don't be a knob.
That inheritance
is rightfully mine!
Rightfully?
I'm his son.
So am I.
Oh.
What?
That can't be true.
You're half...white.
Nice save.
Do you remember
your childhood nanny, Etta?
Well, Etta had
a hot cousin.
My mother.
So you see, Pierce,
I am your half-brother,
and I am more
your father's son
than you ever were,
so shut up and
play the game.
Why you...
Let's go, Pierce.
(WHIZZING)
Okay, look,
I know things
seem hopeless
because he's all the way to
the castle with the crystal
and we're starting over,
but here's the thing...
We're better
at this game now.
We've died and been reborn,
and that makes us heroes.
(ALL CHEERING)
Let's get him!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(DESCENDING TONE)
(FOREBODING MUSIC)
I guess the fact that
we're still playing
means he hasn't won yet.
Yeah, but what's
the point?
He'll just keep cheating
until he wins.
Why are all the trees
cut down?
Isn't this where
Abed's village was?
Hello, old friends.
Abed!
You remember Hilda.
(SPEAKING)
Did she just
say your name?
Yeah, if you max out
a character's trust
and affection levels,
you can gain access
to a front-end
scripting language.
Watch.
(BEEPS)
Cool, cool, cool!
She can make
babies for me.
Oh, and I can't?
I can't.
Come on inside.
I built this from scratch.
Check out my castle.
ANNIE: Oh, it's nice.
JEFF: Wow.
I hope this isn't
blood gold.
(CHILDREN BABBLING)
This is my family.
Baby Abed has my eyes
and her bonnet.
Each baby is capable of
executing custom code,
which means you can
write a code
that makes one baby
tell another baby
what to do,
much like real children
on a playground.
Oh, Abed, but...
Annie, let's find
the tin man's heart later.
Abed, how much stuff
do you have here
and what can we make
with it?
That depends.
On?
On what you can imagine.
BABY ABEDS:
Cool. Cool, cool, cool.
Welcome.
You are the first to make it
to the throne of Hawkthorne.
Let me take a look at you.
According to
your complexion,
I think you might be
Gilbert Lawson.
Is this true?
Just a moment.
Hello, Gilbert.
Due to the nature
of our relationship,
I'll need your
electronic signature
on this legally-binding
agreement.
(MUSICAL TONES)
It dictates that you
will never, ever
besmirch the
Hawthorne name
with any
outlandish notions
regarding your
genealogical origins.
You are
the bastard offspring
of a colored seductress
and an unknown,
weak-willed miscegenist...
It's a simple question,
Gilbert.
Do you agree?
Thank you for being
honest, Gilbert.
No!
I'm your son!
I'm sorry, Gilbert.
I always knew
you'd disappoint me.
BABY ABEDS: Cool, cool,
cool! Cool, cool, cool!
Cool, cool, cool!
Ah, I see
you've chosen teamwork.
A coward's strategy.
I will upgrade
your challenge
accordingly.
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRONIC WHOOSHING)
I bequeath my fortune
to no inferiors.
(ELECTRONIC GUNFIRE)
Yeah!
Attack!
What's this now?
(LAUGHS)
Whoo-hoo, hoo-hoo!
Here we go!
Get him!
Aim for the joints!
BABY ABEDS: Cool, cool,
cool! Cool, cool, cool!
Take that!
Get him!
Die, racism!
(GROANS)
(ELECTRONIC GUNFIRE)
TROY AND ABED:
♪ Troy and Abed
shooting lava ♪
(LAUGHTER)
Yeah!
(GROANING)
Take that!
(LAUGHS)
Aah!
Aah! Oh, no! Aah!
(LAUGHS)
Hey!
Look at me now, Dad!
(THUNK)
Aah!
(GROANS)
(BOULDERS CRASHING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
I suppose
you're wondering, player,
why record myself
breathing weird
and letting you destroy me.
Because I am
a man of honor.
So you've earned
the pleasure of my death.
But I didn't.
I'm not the one
that beat you.
PIERCE: Yes, you are.
We're forfeiting.
AUTOMATED VOICE:  Warning.
Player forfeit in 30 seconds.
PIERCE:
Gilbert, you're right.
You were more his son
than me.
You took all his crap
and you didn't even
get to take his name.
He once sat on me in church
just so he could see better.
We've only been
playing this game
a couple of hours.
You've been playing it
your whole life,
and now it's time
for your reward, brother.
So get in there
and kill our dad.
Thank you, Pierce.
Wait a second.
Here, take this.
(GASPS) Oh!
Whoa!
You may need it.
Oh, Pierce.
You really don't know how
this works, do you?
Are you always
carrying that?
Not in the shower.
(SIGHS)
(CLICK, EXPLOSION)
(WINNING MUSIC PLAYING)
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
I'd like to thank you
again for today
and offer my apologies
for my conduct.
I wasn't myself.
Family can make a person
do a lot of crazy things.
I understand.
I have an uncle who
makes his own pizza.
Don't worry about it.
Yeah, totally.
If it would make it up
to any of you in any way,
there's a bar in town
called Skeepers,
and I hear they make
a specialty drink...
A margarita, in fact,
and it's served in a glass
an entire yard long.
My treat.
Score.
PIERCE:
This is the greatest day
of my life.
I've always wanted
to have a brother.
Hey, hey,
settle a bet.
The word "mulatto,"
Is it okay or
just borderline?
We apologize for him.
GILBERT:
Oh, that's okay.
He's family.
(TYPING)
Hilda, my love, I said
I'd come back for you.
(BABY BABBLING)
ABED: I don't know.
I just think that
in a parallel universe,
blorgons are...
Hold on.
A baby.
I wasn't expecting this.
Guess we'll have to
support it.
I guess I could get
some kind of job,
maybe at Beans and More.
I'll probably have to work
double shifts, but...
Oh, I see.
While you're off,
climbing the ladder
at Beans and More,
I'll just stay home
and raise him alone.
That's fine. I'll just
give up on my dreams.
Here we go.
What?
He needs to learn
a strong man can cry.
So, what were you saying
about blorgons?
Blorgons...
In this other universe,
they're actually
called glorbons.