WOMAN:  A new day has
dawned at Greendale
Community College.
Some said
we'd never bounce back
after the unfortunate events
of the star-burns wake riot
instigated by
the Greendale seven.
But today
the guilty parties
have been expelled,
enrollment is up,
and tuition is more
affordable than ever.
The architect of
this modern-day miracle?
Security chief
Benjamin Franklin Chang,
a man who has
brought security, harmony,
and success to what
is fast becoming
the area's premier
community college.
Greendale's
never been better.
Thanks, Chang.
You see?
It's not the real dean.
Of course.
The head of security at
Greendale community college
has kidnapped the dean
and replaced him with
a deanel-ganger.
Well, when you
say it that way,
it sounds ridiculous.
Yeah, the word we used
was doppel-deaner.
Look, I hate cops.
You have to
do something.
Isn't this a felony?
Chang is holding a man
against his will.
The real dean
never would have
expelled us.
He loved us.
Unfortunately, love is
not admissible evidence.
Oh.
♪ Love is not
admissible evidence ♪
I'm working
on a cop opera.
ALL: Cop-ra!
Police-ical!
Fine.
We'll get some proof.
No, you won't.
If I catch any of you
within 50 feet of Greendale,
I'll throw you all in jail.
Thanks for the hot water.
Wait, cop-ra!
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
I'm watching you.
Move along.
How's the planning
going for my birthday
Chang-stravaganza?
The magician's booked,
and the invitations went out
to the school board
and the Budweiser frogs.
Perfect.
Yeah, um,
one little snag.
See, we're kind of
running out of money,
what with all the
students dropping out
and the cost of your throne.
It's a prescription throne.
I have back mumps.
Don't look it up.
It's rare.
But you might be right.
We should free up
some revenue for
entertainment at the party.
Where's my deanel-Chang-er?
Fire the custodial staff.
Okay. Cool.
Do you think I could
get out a little early?
My wife's getting
her braces off, and...
No.
Okay.
I love how binoculars
make far away things
seem like they're close.
They're like...
BOTH: Telephones
for your eyes.
Snagged one
of those flyers.
(GASPS) First Chang
kidnaps the dean,
and now he throws himself
a birthday party?
It's just like Stalin
back in Russia times.
Dance-off?
Sundae bar?
One of those Ed Hardy
street magicians?
What kind of
monster would...
(GASPS)
Photo booth with props!
Chang's got to be holding
the dean on campus,
but there's no way we're
gonna get past those guards.
We need somebody
on the inside.
I may know a guy.
And the air-conditioning
repair annex won't admit
to any knowledge
of what's going on.
But the fact is,
wherever there is air,
we have eyes.
Gross.
Suffice it to say,
if Chang were holding
your dean captive,
it'd be pretty foolish
to hold him on campus.
It'd be even
more foolish to hold him
in a central air room
in the cafeteria,
which we monitor.
Oh, no, Jeffrey.
Looks like PB and J again.
You win the bet. (LAUGHS)
So he's in
the cafeteria building?
Suppose he is.
In the basement.
And suppose you
wanted to get to him.
Suppose you actually
managed to make it
past the guards
at the front,
there's 50 more inside,
armed to the teeth
with stun batons
and misplaced
sexual aggression.
Let's say you happen
to get past them
and then you get to meet
Chang's number one,
Joshua,
a 4'10", 105-pound bucket
of piss and zit cream.
I cannot express
to you how much
I hate this kid.
Now, beyond
that dog sneeze
in a pair of Reeboks,
you're gonna find
a state-of-the-art keypad
on the basement door.
And just for extra fun,
they change the code
every day,
and the only copy is
locked up in Chang's office.
Now, just for a lark,
let's pretend you
actually make it down
to the basement door.
Who is there to greet you?
Another guard
and another lock
to which there is
only one key.
And where is that key?
Well, where is it?
Oh, sorry,
it's very clear in my head.
Key's around Chang's neck.
The point is,
you're not getting down
there without our help.
So help us.
We have
no horse in this race,
but there is
one thing we want.
Not a lot of people
get a second chance.
Just you
and probably Obama.
Give it some thought.
Great, so according
to Troy's intel,
Greendale is impregnable.
So what do we do?
Only one answer.
Elaborate heist?
We'll need disguises.
I do a great swami.
Of course it works
best with a cobra,
but if you guys cut me
a length of garden hose...
Are we all forgetting
that if we get caught
on that campus,
we go to jail?
Do you know
how long someone
as sarcastic as I am
would last in prison?
Such a long time.
There's got to be
a practical way to do this.
There is another way in.
If I enroll
in the AC school,
they'll help us.
We could walk in and out.
It'll mean I'll have
to move out of here
and into
AC school housing,
and I won't be
able to hang out
with you guys anymore,
or have a relationship,
or use the word "sensational"
for some reason.
Troy, we are
not losing you
to save the dean
or Greendale.
Or anything, ever.
Don't be so
dramatic, Troy.
The answer is simple.
We just have to plan
an elaborate heist.
Yes.
Great, I'll get my turban.
Everyone except Pierce has
to plan an elaborate heist.
CARL: Happy birthday, Ben.
On behalf
of the school board.
Shower organizer?
Are you guys psychic?
Well, you deserve it.
You have
worked wonders here.
Oh, you boners.
Now go party
your butts off.
Your butt
could use it, Richie.
(LAUGHING OBNOXIOUSLY)
Listen up, men.
Keep an extra deep lookout
for the Greendale seven.
I won't
have them ruining
my 25th birthday.
Yes, sir.
By the way,
your cake just arrived.
Shirley will enter first
through the loading dock
disguised as the chef.
From there, she'll head
into the kitchen.
You had time to build
a tiny working water fountain,
and I'm a pinecone?
♪ Chang eats the sun
♪ And drinks the skies
♪ And they both go
with him when he dies ♪
JEFF:  Once in,
she'll unload the goods.
This girl in Chicago
won't stop Facebooking me.
Looks like J-swag's
going deep dish.
JEFF:  Then it's time
for phase two,
toilet trouble.
Oh, crap!
Someone call a plumber!
Sounds like
you schnooks got a flood
the size of my wife's
attitude problem.
Whoa, you guys aren't
the usual plumbers.
Oh, Mr. Brand loyalty
over here.
Okay, okay,
why don't you
two slap-arounds
give me your names
for the report
in case Chang wants to know
why his birthday party
turned into the frickin'
Poseidon Adventure.
Okay, okay.
Follow me then.
Finally.
Oof baboof with you two.
Here's your problem.
You people gotta
start chewin' your food.
We may have to tap into
the hydraulic flap valve,
so don't be alarmed
if things get
a little noisy.
Like my wife's mouth.
JEFF:  If we can break
through this wall
and into Chang's office,
then we'll have access
to the basement door codes.
Meanwhile, I'll take care
of cancelling the magician.
Yeah, sorry,
Mr. Nightshade,
gig's canceled.
How's it coming
with the guard?
Boys are pathetic.
Two days of Facebooking
with this Joshua kid
and he's eating
out of my hands.
"Got a new
flavor of lip balm.
"Meet me at Chili's
in 10 minutes."
Sheep.
Um, I just
want to reiterate
that this should be
the only time you seduce
a child over the internet.
I know.
Chili's? Sick!
Hey, bro,
you watch my post?
Yeah, whatever. 'Sup.
I'm in.
Cue the abra cadabra.
Is that me
in my swami disguise?
No, Pierce,
for the last time,
you're in the getaway van
because your swami act
is notoriously horrible.
A, that is racist.
B, swamis can't drive,
they're indians.
Pierce, just do your part.
Leave the entertainment
to Britta and me.
(GASPS)
Ricky Nightshade,
the rock and roll magician.
I'm starting.
I need a volunteer.
I'll kill anyone
who raises their hand.
(GIGGLES)
Pick a card
and look at it.
Strap him!
(THUDDING)
I'm in.
(SQUEALING)
Okay, it was
just my head before,
but now I'm really in.
Bingo.
4-1-2-6.
(LOCK CLICKS)
I'm in.
Where's the key?
I know.
Well, everybody
else got to say it.
(WHOOPING)
Is this your card?
Huh?
I don't remember.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(LAUGHS)
Nightshade, Nightshade!
Greetings, greetings,
Baba Ghanoush.
Take me to the birthday boy.
Wait a minute.
Pierce?
(LAUGHS)
No, not knowing this Pierce.
I am a mystical swami.
I come to boogie down,
I'm boogying down.
Hey!
(CROWD GASPS)
Jeff, we've been made.
Cover me!
Winger!
Huh? No!
Everything all right, Ben?
Peachy keen,
Avril Lavigne.
BEN: Nathan, tell me
you got eyes on the dean.
Negative, the pixie
has left the toadstool.
No! Where's my monitor?
Gotcha.
Code Chang.
All units
converge on the
south library hallway.
JEFF:  The best
part of the plan is
that at a certain point,
it's going to look like
the plan is failing.
But that's when
it's going to turn out
that the failing plan
was all part of the plan.
♪ Chang eats the sun
♪ And drinks the sky ♪
Hey, Johnny passerby,
this job's getting bigger
than my wife's
credit card bill
at Marshalls.
I mean,
they got great stuff,
I know that.
Anyway, I'm going to need
your dean for approval.
Craig.
Is that "A-I" or "I-A"?
I always forget.
(SHOUTS)
Oof baboof,
I spilled plumber's
acid all over yous.
What do I do?
Take off your clothes.
Nathan, tell me
you got eyes on the dean.
Negative, the pixie
has left the toadstool.
Repeat, the pixie
Jeffrey!
Oh. Hey, Britta.
How the Chang?
I'm contaminated
with plumber's acid,
but it's okay,
they're coming back
with a lotion.
(RHYTHMICALLY)
Sarcastic claps.
Pretty clever.
A plan that looked
like it failed,
and then
turned out to work.
Too bad your real plan
really failed.
(CHUCKLES)
What's so funny?
You idiot.
The plan was for the plan
to seem like it was failing.
You think you caught us,
but we've already made it
out with the real dean.
Ocean's Eleven, baby.
Pierce,
I'm the real dean.
Getting caught
the first time was
part of the plan.
This time is
because we suck.
Shirley, where the hell
did you come from?
You can't
hold us here forever.
I don't need to, Winger.
I just wouldn't want
you to leave before
the big fireworks show.
Fireworks show?
It's a surprise
for the end of the night
planned by the "dean."
Only, silly dean,
he stored all the fireworks
in the records room. Aw.
And when the works
"accidentally" go off
when I hit the final note
on my awesome keytar solo,
they'll burn up
the school's records
and all evidence
of my misdeeds.
Chang, you're insane.
You're still into keytar?
We're going to tell
the board what you did!
(MOCKINGLY)
We're going to
tell the board...
You think they'll believe
the Greendale seven
and the worst dean ever
over the guy who just
nailed an awesome solo?
You're going to
burn down the school
and kill everyone!
Fire can't go
through doors, stupid.
It's not a ghost.
I know this is
a bit of a long shot,
but I don't suppose
any of you paid my rent?
Thank you,
everyone, for joining
in my celebration.
As many of you know,
I ate my twin sister
in utero.
So on my birthday,
I try to remember
I'm a winner.
This one's
for you, Connie.
(LAUGHING WICKEDLY)
And a-one, a-two,
a Chang, Chang, Chang-four.
(PLAYING  AXEL F)
We're all going to die.
We have to get out of here.
How?
(SQUEAKING)
It's a miracle.
Let's get out of here!
Oh, my God!
Yes!
Come on, come on, come on.
No, Troy, you didn't...
There's no time.
We gotta go.
(PLAYING RAPIDLY)
Six guards,
two on scooters.
Chang started his solo.
Knowing him,
that gives us
only nine minutes
to get to
the records room.
We'll need a distraction.
You heard the lady.
Take your tops off.
I might have something.
To supplement
Greendale's budget,
I've been renting
the school out for
raves on the weekend.
They call it academania.
It's mostly hard house,
some dubstep,
but totally...
Perfect.
Troy and Abed,
you make a run for it.
Dean, I think
it's time to party.
Hmm.
Hey, what the freak?
(ELECTRONIC DANCE MUSIC)
BOY: What's going on?
(SCREAMS)
No! No! No!
You weigh nothing!
I can't see them.
They're too many of them.
Oof.
Baboof.
Which wire do I cut?
There's only one.
God, I hope I'm right.
Study group!
You did it!
So we're done, right?
We're done?
Done, done, done?
Not done.
You foiled me
for the last time.
(LAUGHING WICKEDLY)
So, it ends as it began.
It didn't begin this way.
What the hell's
going on in here?
Hey, fellas.
I just caught
the Greendale seven
trying to burn down
the school.
I'm a hero.
How about that cake?
He's lying.
He kidnapped the dean.
Yeah, we gathered that much
when we found these two
slap-fighting
in the hallway.
You stole my life!
It is hard out there
for a fake Moby!
Carl, Richie,
let me ex-Chang.
I'm not getting
paid, am I?
Hey!
So a madman
in a napoleon costume
ran the school
into the ground
and almost blew it up?
Yeah.
And on our watch.
What happened to us?
Well, I have
a drinking problem.
We're going to get fired.
Only a matter of time
until everyone finds out
what happened here.
Nobody can sit
on something this big.
I'll sit on it.
When I became dean,
I made a pledge
to swallow
this school's failures
and spit out degrees
because that's
what deans do.
You'd do that for us?
No.
I do it for Greendale.
GIRLS: Aw.
It's great to
have you back, Craig.
It's almost as if you were
never unknowingly gone.
Yard margs at 'Skeeper's.
(LAUGHS)
Perfect. I left
my credit card there.
Thanks, Craig.
You guys saved me.
I don't know
how I will ever repay you.
You already have.
(GROANS)
Troy, you don't
have to do this.
The AC school has
no claim on your soul.
No, but I do.
A man's only as good
as his word,
or his nod through a camera
to a guy with a button.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
It's time.
Say your good-byes.
Shirley, never change.
Or do, if you want,
I'm not your boss.
Oh, honey.
(WHIMPERS)
(SIGHS)
Never wear a rubber.
Never listen to Pierce.
When you finally finish
that jigsaw puzzle,
will you tell me
what kind of boat is
at the end of that dock?
This is a lock of my hair.
Creepy.
(WHISPERING)
All right, let's go.
Abed?
What did he say to you?
He said, "I know
you hate when people
do this in movies."
Sorry I got emotional.
Troy Barnes.
Welcome home.
Whoo!
I'm really digging
this hard house!
It's quite a groove.
This is my school!
It's called Greendale,
and I'm the dean
of the entire school.
I mean,
I wasn't for a while,
but it's a long story.
You guys, everybody,
you should come by
during the day sometime.
It's totally different.
Really, stop by.
It'll blow your minds.
You can meet
my best friend, Jeffrey.
Sure,
I'll take a back rub.
Who's asking?