And Andre's
going as Han Solo.
Oh!
The boys
are storm troopers
and little baby Ben
is an Ewok.
Oh!
Aw, you don't
have enough children.
Happy Halloween parties,
everyone.
You all look great...
Ham.
Pig.
Let me guess.
You're a flimsy excuse
to be shirtless,
wearing silk underwear.
And you are
as wrong
as you are welcome.
Now, this year,
I planned
a two person costume
with Annie.
She's going
as my ring girl.
(ALL SCREAM)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Pretty freakydeaky, huh?
Annie, no.
I meant the boxing match
ring girl.
They're the sexy ones
that hold the round numbers.
Yeah, see?
This is why
we can't just text
about it, Jeff.
I don't watch sports.
But there's no boxer
in  The Ring.
Yeah, well,
I don't watch
scary movies.
And that's why
we leave
the couples' costumes
to the couples,
she said wisely.
You should probably warn
your boyfriend's boyfriend.
Just because
we're dating
doesn't mean
that we have to do
everything together.
Well, you need to do
some things together.
We do some things.
We do a lot of things.
(GASPS)
Not all the things.
Things.
Okay, so, we're all here...
(PHONE RINGING)
minus Pierce,
who wasn't invited
to Vicki's party
for reasons
beyond our control
or concern.
No mystery there.
She put a pencil
through his face.
(LAUGHTER)
Does Vicki have a TV?
Abed, it's a party.
You're not watching TV.
No, I'll be
watching  Annie.
She started watching
Cougar Town reruns,
which makes  Annie
my third favorite show,
and tonight
is their
Hallowine special.
Ooh, that's right.
Better not
miss the merlot.
Clink!
What? You fall into it.
That was Pierce.
He accidentally
locked himself
in his panic room
and he needs our help.
ALL: Oh!
No, "Oh!"
"Oh" means we are going
against our will,
and we are not going.
He's lying.
He seemed pretty upset,
and he's been all alone
up there in that mansion
ever since I moved out,
and his dad,
you know,
got killed by Jeff.
Hmm, calling for help.
A classic call for help.
Hello, Dr. Perry's office.
Damaged psyche?
Yes,
I'll accept the charges.
Heads,
lock up your brains.
Britta's on the prowl
for fresh therapy meat.
Maybe we should just
stop by on our way
to the party.
I assure you,
the only thing Pierce
is trapped in is adolescence.
He is
a geriatric toddler,
throwing the most
elaborate tantrums
money can buy,
and I, for one,
am not gonna stand by
and allow some lonely,
ridiculous person
to derail
our group's plans.
Ding, ding, ding!
To your corners, fighters.
Someone save me
a towel. (LAUGHS)
You guys going
to Vicki's party?
We just gotta
do this thing first.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Oh.
Holy Helen,
this place is huge.
It seems spookier
than I remember.
Ah, the only thing spooky
about this place
is the tacky decor.
It's like David Lee Roth
threw up  Miami Vice.
(GROANS)
So tacky.
I don't know.
Maybe Pierce
isn't doing so well
since he lost his father
and then his inheritance
in a video game battle
with Gilbert,
an illegitimate half brother
he never knew he had.
I guess I've never
said it out loud.
Guys, over here.
Mr. Hawthorne's
panic room,
one of the 27 stops
on the guided tour
I had to memorize
before moving into
Hawthorne Manor.
Does the house
get many visitors?
You're the first.
Impenetrable
titanium carbonite door,
hackerproof keycode
access panel,
and impressive
video telecom screen
with remote.
Maximum occupancy one,
with female companion.
Purchased June 30, 1989.
It took me forever
to remember that date.
June 30, 1989.
Theatrical release
of  Do the Right Thing.
Oh!
Oh.
Wait!
It might be a trap.
Or it might
let him out.
Either way, we...
Oh, put a sock
in it, shorts.
(CLICK)
(MUSICAL FANFARE)
Oh, hey, guys.
Pierce,
are you okay?
Oh, sure.
Fine, fine.
I was dusting in here,
and I must have
bumped a switch
or something.
As the graceful one
in the group,
I'm kind of embarrassed.
Don't be.
I've been locked in
way worse places than this.
Oh, not against
my will.
Been in there long?
No, not long,
but I couldn't remember
the damn code.
Sorry to be a burden
on you guys,
but I guess
that's all I am now.
Oh!
It's okay.
We're happy to help.
Yeah, no sweat,
Boba Fett.
Yeah.
Do you have a TV?
What Abed means is,
did you write
the code down anywhere?
Yes. It's in
a red notebook
in my study
or my bedroom, maybe.
I used to know
where everything was
before I fired my maid.
Now there's no reason
to use my safe.
That's okay.
We'll find it.
It'll take two secs.
Or we take one sec
and just skip to the catch.
This place
has not been dusted
in months,
and he starts
with the panic room?
No sale.
He's not a sad old man.
He's a sad old liar.
Jeffrey!
No, no, he's right.
I've been lying to you.
The truth is,
last night,
I got up
to get a glass
of red, uh, water,
and on my way back
from the cellar,
I saw something
that scared me so badly,
I locked myself in here,
on purpose.
The part about
not remembering the code
is true.
I'm very thirsty.
Why didn't you
call me sooner?
I had to come up
with that awesome
dusting story
because if you knew
what spooked me,
you'd probably
call me crazy and old.
No one's
gonna call you, Pierce.
You can tell us.
We're here to help you.
I thought I saw my dad.
Oh!
It looked like his face
was coming right through
the wall,
but that's impossible,
because my dad is dead.
Aha!
I mean, not, aha,
your dad is dead,
but, aha, I knew it.
Ghost dad,
exploring
your haunted mansion
for secret codes?
Nice try, Pierce.
You gotta...
...be kidding me!
What in the Scooby Doo
is happening to you people?
Jeff, just go to the party,
and we'll meet you there.
We're gonna stay here
and help Pierce.
He doesn't need help.
He needs attention.
Are you really
this naive?
Am I naive?
I'm sure as stuff not
your sexy little ring girl.
I...
Can it, Ham.
She's also my ride.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Troy said...
Pierce's bedroom
is the third door
on the left.
I didn't leave
my short term memory
at Coachella.
Jeez, Winger,
keep it above the belt.
I'm sorry.
Ah, already forgotten.
This house
is getting to me.
I know. Kind of weird
that a dead person
used to live here.
No, what's weird
is that a living person
lived here
with his parents,
well into his 60s.
Then they died,
and he's still here,
like a paralyzed Peter Pan.
Not for long.
I'm gonna set my shrink ray
to daddy issues
and blast that sucker
full of closure.
Well, I guess
it can't hurt.
Exactly, because,
in one way or another,
therapy is always helpful.
No, because
there's no possible way
you could
mess him up worse.
It's like practicing
on a cadaver.
Knock yourself out.
This has got to be it.
Ugh.
I wish I didn't have
so much exposed skin.
(SHUDDERS)
Agh.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Tubular.
I, too,
lack the adjectives.
Now, how does one search
for a red notebook
that doesn't exist
without looking,
touching or creating
future nightmares?
I'll check
the nightstand.
JEFF: I'll check
my messages.
Oh, my God.
Pierce keeps
his dad's bowtie
by his bed.
Yeesh.
Table for Siggy Freud,
party of...
Britta,
stop answering phones.
How about we ask
Rip Van Racism
where the codes are?
Don't. That's not nice.
What?
He was a tightfisted,
philandering bigot
who got to outlive
most bridges.
We don't owe him
our reverence.
So, how about it,
you old bag of dust?
You got our numbers?
(WIND BLOWING)
I'm serious. Stop it.
Come on.
You don't really
believe in ghosts?
I don't know.
I'm just not so quick
to rule it out.
I believe people
can be haunted
by unresolved issues
in their past.
Yeah, but issues
don't turn into ghosts.
Maybe for Pierce,
they have.
Maybe Pierce
and his dad
have some seriously
unfinished business.
No, the dead
can't have business.
They can't want
or think or do.
It's what
makes them dead.
It's the living
who choose to be haunted.
Cornelius
was barely a dad.
Now, he's nothing.
And Pierce keeps staring
into that void
or he can turn around,
face his future like I did,
and say,
"Who gives a crap
who my dad was?
"I'm my own man now.
I..."
Wow.
Pretty slick, Britta,
using ghosts to trick me
into opening up.
Too bad it didn't work.
Aw, man,
so this is what
the zone feels like.
Oh!
Analyze this!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
We don't want to go
over the same area twice,
so be thorough.
Thorough. Got it.
(GASPS)
More of a burnt umber,
but I won't hold that
against him.
"Pierce Hawthorne's
ideas for ladies?"
Oh, please.
"Blonde, long legs,
with tennis racquet.
"Asian rockette.
"Big boobs, redhead,
but doctor," question mark.
Oh, he's not 100%
on that one?
This is the greatest thing
that has ever happened to me.
Okay,
I don't have the codes.
Maybe Shirley and Troy
are having better luck
in the library.
Abed?
If this is
supposed to be, like,
that part in that movie
that's like this,
I would like to remind you
that I don't watch
scary movies
and therefore
cannot appreciate
the homage.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(BUZZING STOPS)
Abed?
Ah!
(GASPS)
I hate reference humor.
Hold on.
I've been offended
by this coat rack before.
Are we going
in circles?
Okay,
so maybe I spent
a little less time
in the library
than, say,
the walkin cereal closet,
but it's definitely
near here.
You skipped this door.
Pierce told me
I don't need to
go in there.
Then it's probably
the library.
Racist son of a...
Sodom and Gomorrah.
It's Pierce's
special gym.
He never let me use it,
'cause he thinks
I'm a child.
Hold...
He's hiding
the indoor swing,
and I'm the child.
No.
Troy, get out of there.
Why does he have
so many collars?
Secret dogs!
Oh, it's okay.
Come on.
TROY: Oh, no.
Forget you saw that,
and then forget
I knew what it was.
Great, you won't tell me,
Pierce won't tell me.
I have no idea
what to Google.
I'll never know.
Believe me,
dating Britta,
you'll know too much
too soon
soon enough.
What does Britta
have to do with this?
Well, she's a modern woman
with experienced tastes.
I think it's nice
you two are dating.
I only hope she doesn't
make you feel pressured.
Pressured to what?
To fulfill
her expectations.
Expectations of what?
(LAUGHS)
Never mind.
Unsatisfied with what?
(DOOR HANDLE RATTLES)
(GASPS)
(RATTLING)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
BOTH: Whoa!
I lost Abed.
I turned around
and he disappeared.
I told you to never
let him out of your sight.
That goes double
for holidays
and wax museums.
How are we gonna
find him?
I don't know,
but we have to.
He's probably
already looking for us.
WOMAN:  Oh, well,
that's Hallowine
in Cougar Town  for ya.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, ladies,
I'll follow you anywhere.
JEFF:  I do not have
daddy issues.
You get two minutes.
Denial is the first step
to acceptance.
That can't be right.
Says the denyist.
Not a word.
You want to keep
digging this hole?
Confronting
your daddy issues now
could prevent you
from ending up haunted,
like Pierce.
I'll never end up
Won't you?
No, because
I'm nothing like him.
Aren't you?
Are you gonna
keep doing that?
Am I?
The worst therapist? No.
Because you're not
a therapist.
But since
your misdiagnosing
by a mile,
let me point out
some differences.
Pierce was raised
by his dad.
Mine took off
when I was eight.
Pierce spent his whole,
pathetic life
begging for scraps
of his father's approval.
I moved on.
Maybe Pierce
needs a dad.
I don't.
Don't you?
Stop that!
Okay,
if I need a dad
so bad,
how come I've had
his phone number
for three weeks
without
the slightest urge
to call him?
You found your dad?
Did I?
Give it here!
I remember when this show
was about
a community college.
(WHIRRING)
No, you take
the fish sticks,
Senator.
Enjoy the boat show.
(WHIRRING)
Cool.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Cool, cool, cool.
Just let me see
the number,
for medical purposes!
No!
Help me heal
your heart hole!
Never!
(POUNDING)
So, this is where
Pierce has been
hiding the taste.
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
(EXHALES)
Here's to you,
Cornelius.
Gone,
but not forgiven.
Of course.
Otherwise,
it wouldn't be pointless.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
This is pointless.
We have no Abed,
no codes.
Pierce sent us
on a wild goose chase.
Jeff was right.
I am naive.
Oh,
don't listen to him.
There's nothing naive
about helping
a friend in need.
Jeff would know that
if he wasn't too cool
for afterschool specials.
Thanks, Troy.
Don't worry.
Abed's here.
I can feel him.
Maybe we should
loop back
to the indoor swing room.
Indoor swing?
That's ridiculous.
Someone's gonna
break a lamp.
Break something on it.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Britta, while I applaud
your gentle approach
to psychoanalysis,
I'm not gonna
talk about it.
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
Hey, cut it out!
(LOUDER BANGING)
You're gonna break
the...
...door.
(CLATTER)
(RUMBLING)
Well, look who came
crawling back.
I'm not crawling.
Walking.
Quite briskly.
Follow!
I like talking
to you, Annie.
It's easy.
I hope you feel like
you can talk to me too.
Oh!
Uh, I...
Spit it out.
No secrets
between roomies.
Behind you!
I'm behind you too.
Hands! Wall!
Not sure
where you're going here,
but just let it out.
(BOTH SCREAM)
Ah! Don't let it out!
Don't let it out!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(RENEWED SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
All right, Pierce,
turn off your haunted house!
(MUSICAL FANFARE)
Ah!
Oh, my God,
Pierce is dead.
Cornelius killed him.
I broke the remote!
Do you think
it's expensive?
TROY: Please, Pierce.
Please don't die
slightly before
your time.
This means we're next,
and I care about us.
(BEEPING)
Oh!
Where...
Gotcha!
(ALL SCREAM)
What the hell?
I totally had you guys
convinced I was dead.
That'll teach you
to value my presence.
Pierce.
Don't Pierce me.
You were going to
Vicki's party without me.
Bet you didn't expect me
to fake a haunted house
to teach you a lesson.
That's exactly
what we expected.
For heaven's sake, Pierce,
Vicki's the one
that didn't invite you.
Why didn't you
scare her?
'Cause I hate her.
ANNIE: Abed!
Where have you been?
I found Pierce's
secret surveillance room.
Did you guys know
he was faking
a haunted house?
This has been Abed Nadir
with the late report.
Sorry.
Good montages take time.
PIERCE: Man,
it was so easy.
A few shadows,
a couple of mirror tricks.
A little, custom built
latex walls,
and you're all crappin'
in your short pants.
It was
pretty impressive,
particularly
the shadowy figure
you hired
to watch you sleep.
ANNIE: Wow,
that is creepy.
A standout performance.
Is he sad?
(ALARM BLARING)
What are you doing?
I didn't hire anyone.
Oh, enough, Pierce.
Just open the damn door.
There's no ghost.
Then how do you
explain this?
You probably
asked someone
to help you
with your stupid prank
and then forgot.
Uh-uh. LeVar Burton
was a hard no.
There's only
one explanation.
I belittled my father's
good name for a prank,
and his ghost has returned
to scold me
and probably
butcher you guys
for going along with it.
You think hiding
in this room
is gonna keep you safe?
Ghosts can't go
through doors, stupid.
They're not fire.
Pierce, I am paying
a teenager by the hour
to care about my children
so I can go to this party,
so you have to
ask yourself,
is the real threat
out there
or in here?
Fine.
I'll open it myself.
No, no.
He'll scold me!
(ALARM BEEPS)
Ah!
Someone's punching in
the code from the outside.
Please tell me
one of us is outside.
Oh!
(BEEP)
May I be
of some assistance?
ALL: Gilbert!
Gilbert, what are you
doing in my house?
Well, technically,
it's my house.
After our father died,
I became
the sole inheritor
of his estate,
including all six houses
and the decommissioned
submarine.
What?
So you came here
to kick me out?
Actually, I came here
to give you the deed,
but on the day
of my arrival,
you were out.
I noticed mail piled up
by the door.
I took it in,
paid the overdue bills,
replaced a few
light bulbs,
and, well,
that was six weeks ago.
So you've been living here
in secret this whole time?
Yes.
I'm ashamed to say
that after a lifetime
as Cornelius's assistant,
I've had a difficult time
adjusting to his passing.
It seems his absence
has taken a greater toll
than his presence
ever did.
Taking care of Pierce
gave my life
purpose again,
but now that
I've been discovered
by your thin friend,
I must apologize
and bid you  adieu.
Goodbye, Pierce.
There's a load
of clean socks
in the dryer.
Gilbert, wait. Wait.
Look, I've been doing
really well
since Dad died,
so I don't need anyone
taking care of me,
but if you're having
a tough time...
(SIGHS)
Well, I guess
I could use
a roommate.
Will there be
anything else, brother?
Yes. Bring it in.
Oh.
PIERCE: Have fun
at the party.
Tell Vicki I say
Happy Halloween.
That'll mess with her.
You sure
you don't want to come?
I've got a mask
for you to wear.
One that doesn't zip
at the mouth.
No, thanks.
I'll hang around here
with Gilbert.
He needs me.
Oh, that's nice.
What was all that
about masks?
Don't know,
don't want to.
Fair enough.
Hey, how about you and I
skip out on this party?
Why? To do what
and where?
Oh, I was thinking
you could show me
some  Inspector Spacetime.
You're always
talking about it.
I've never seen
a full episode.
Oh, are you sure
you want to?
It starts pretty slow.
The first inspector
couldn't even time travel.
Uh!
That sounds fine.
After a night
of running in circles,
trying to untie
Winger knots,
I'm looking
for something slow.
Sorry I ruined
your night.
Actually,
Pierce ruined my night,
but you were right
to let him.
You still want to go
to the party?
I heard Vicki
bought dry ice
and gave Leonard
the wrong address.
Uh, I'll take a pass.
Oh.
I have some
unfinished business
at home.
(MELLOW POP MUSIC)
Troy!
Are you in here?
Abed, was that you?
I want to show you something
on the other side
of the bookcase.
Troy?
Find me
as soon as you can.
Who is in my house?
Gilbert!
Hijinks.
Indubitably.
Did it work?
Are you tall?