(BLORGONS SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
Take that, Blorgon.
Good show, Inspector.
Oh, wow, there are
50 years of these, huh?
Yeah, isn't it great?
We can go anywhere
and any time
in the universe.
But it will
probably be London
during the Blitz.
Oh, I think I finally
got Abed to agree
to let you come
to the Inspector Spacetime
Convention.
Yay.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Are you watching
Inspector Spacetime?
Why does he have
to wake up so early?
Can't we just tell Abed
that we're sleeping
together?
No. No. Abed's fragile.
We have to ease him
into it, okay?
Do we want him to freak out
and then we have
to rescue him
from some fantasy world
where submarines
are small enough
to enter
the bloodstream?
I totally want
to do that.
We need to go over
the convention
schedule again.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Just a minute.
Troy, it's a week away,
and we need to revise
our whole strategy.
Mwah.
Troy, I've printed out
several maps of
the convention center
and color-coded
the best potential routes.
Now we know I have
a longer stride,
but I'm assuming
your superior
physical fitness
will allow you
to compensate
with greater speed.
One thing's for sure,
though.
We need to save time
by changing into
our costumes in the car.
Curling iron.
Thanks.
ABED: Coming.
Hi, Abed.
Just here for
my breakfast date
with Troy.
Oh, good morning, Britta.
I haven't seen you
in over 12 hours.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
I know you two
are having sex.
I've known for weeks.
What?
Why didn't you
say something?
I love doughnuts.
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
I just need to
get my sunglasses,
and then we can go.
We're gonna be late,
and you don't
need sunglasses
to go to an Inspector
Spacetime Convention.
You're right.
For an Inspector
Spacetime Convention,
I would need a bag
to put over my head.
But Annie and I
are going skiing.
That is the only reason
I agreed to this road trip.
(BOTH SCREAM)
What are you
doing here?
I always come early
to save my seat.
And what's this
about a road trip?
Look, Pierce,
no one was trying
to leave you out.
We just assumed
you wouldn't be interested.
Which is why
we left you out.
That's not fair.
Why can't I go to
a Captain Warptime
Convention?
Because you'll ruin it.
I'm getting sick
of everyone assuming
that I have nothing
to offer.
You know,
in ancient Greece,
it was considered
an honor to invite
a person my age
to a space convention?
We didn't invite Shirley
either.
Well, that's better then.
All right.
BOTH: Good night.
Good night.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
I can't believe it...
Our first Inspecticon.
It's beautiful.
Now are you sure
it's okay Britta's here?
Because she can just wait
in the car.
It's cool.
Now the first thing
we need to do
is find the booth
where they take
the gluon photo.
It's a photo
where two people
are fused together
like the Inspector and
Reggie were bonded
for eternity
in episode 704.
BOTH: Oh.
Wait, was there
a female inspector?
Yes. And everyone
hates her.
Not because they're sexist.
Because she sucks.
Well, I think it's cool.
Britta.
Annie.
You're on your own,
Al Capone.
Everyone's entitled
to their own opinion.
Am I the only one
freaked out by that?
No, I think Abed
was just showing
that he's accepting
of our relationship.
No, really.
What was it?
Hey, Annie, sad news.
They closed
the ski slopes.
A dozen scouts got buried
in an avalanche.
So sad.
I say we cut our losses
and head home.
What?
Why? We're already here.
We can still have fun
hanging out at
the convention.
I'd have more fun
hanging out
with the parents
that are circling
the block.
Jeff, why are people
staring at you?
Because they've never seen
a man who's had sex before?
All right, how many of those
do you have in your chamber?
Enough for
the whole ride home.
(SNICKERING)
Jeff.
What?
We wanted it
to be a surprise.
You bear
a striking resemblance
to  Inspector Spacetime's
supervillain Thoraxis.
Okay. Now we're
definitely leaving.
But I've never been
on an adult vacation before.
This is the first time
I've stayed in a hotel
without a number
in its name.
Hey, you can stay
if you want.
Fine.
I'll be in my room.
Good.
The reservation's
under my name.
Enjoy the nerds.
I will enjoy the...
Jeff won.
I know.
Abed, the gluon photo line
looks really long.
We should probably
get in it now.
Definitely.
Right after I find Toby.
Who's Toby?
(CHUCKLES)
Toby Weeks.
Arguably the biggest
Inspector Spacetime fan
in the world.
We've been emailing
for months.
Oh. You never
mentioned him.
Well, you've been
so busy lately having sex.
Besides, we talked
about embracing change,
so I'm expanding
my social circle.
I just hope he makes it.
He works in Nigeria
in banking.
He almost
couldn't come because
all his money was tied up
in this financial thing,
but I sent him 700 pounds
and a plane ticket,
so he should be here.
Oh, Abed.
There he is.
You must be Abed.
Inspector.
Ooh, before I forget,
here is your check.
Thanking you very much
indeed.
Nice.
You wouldn't believe
how many people
I emailed asking for help,
and they completely
ignored me.
Hmm.
Toby, this is Britta.
Fraulein.
And my best friend Troy.
And where's
your constable?
Oh, my best friend Andrew.
He was supposed to come,
but then his wife
wouldn't let him go
at the last minute.
She's such a...
BOTH: Minerva.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
oh, Minerva.
What a bitch.
Wait, was that
the female inspector?
Not in front of Toby.
Hey, gluon line,
we should probably
get in it right now.
Alternatively,
someone might just happen
to have a pair of tickets
to the sold-out panel,
"Which Inspector would win
in a fight in space,
"and which Inspector
would win in a fight
in time?"
We can get
that photo later.
Yeah, later.
That was when I wanted
to take it.
Are you sure Troy and Abed
want us here?
They do. They just
don't know it yet.
Now, remember,
we're just a couple of
Captain Warphead fans.
Nobody will even notice
we're here.
Excuse me.
No... Yes?
Will you come with us?
Where? Why? When?
Okay.
MAN ON PHONE:
Room service.
Yes, I'd like
to order some food.
And how many people will be
dining today, Mrs. Winger?
Oh, I'm not...
Two.
Yeah, I'd like
a turkey burger
and a second turkey burger,
but with no bun.
My husband
doesn't do carbs.
But he would
like a scotch.
And what kind of scotch
would your husband prefer?
The good kind.
I'll see what we can do.
Yes, Mrs. Winger?
Excuse me,
I don't mean
to bother you,
but are you
Nigel Cuthbertson,
the actor
who played Thoraxis?
(BAD BRITISH ACCENT)
Call me Nige.
We have every right
to be here,
and I don't know
if you're being sexist,
ageist, racist,
or what,
but I don't think
I like your -ist.
Actually,
we need your help.
We're focus-testing
a new American version
of  Inspector Spacetime,
and you two represent
several significant
quadrants.
Oh, I don't know.
Your thoughts would be
very valuable to us.
We're in.
Toby, did you see...
The Christmas special?
Horrible.
But when you consider
what it set up...
Brilliant.
Is that...
Let's go.
What about the photo?
Do they even
have to talk?
They could just
touch tentacles
and download.
You know, this is good,
because, you know,
Abed's branching out,
and Toby's really,
really great.
No. Troy,
I have seen that look.
Girls have
given me that look.
You are not being crazy.
That dude is trying
to steal your boyfriend.
I'm gonna get a refill.
What if Abed wants
to replace me?
It makes me
so angry and sad
all at the same time.
I know, but
you have to hide it,
because,
for some reason,
men find these feelings
to be psycho,
and, if you freak out,
it's only gonna
push Abed away.
Like I always say,
if you love someone,
set them free, and,
if they don't come back
to you,
they were never yours
to begin with.
That makes no sense.
What if they get
hit by a car
or fall down a well?
Remind me not to
put you down as
my emergency contact.
All right.
Play it cool.
Make nice with Toby.
Yeah.
(ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYS)
So?
What did everyone think?
I thought
it was pretty good.
I was confused.
And what confused you?
The time travel mostly.
Also the space travel.
Anything else?
How many
clipboards you got?
Raise the klaxon.
Me lorry's plunging it
into the Thames, methinks.
(LAUGHTER)
Hey, do you mind
if I practice
my American accent?
I have an audition.
Of course.
You really are
an  Inspector Spacetime fan.
Ever since I was little.
What is it you like
about the show?
I think
the show's philosophy poses
some really interesting...
Questions about the nature...
Bow before Thoraxis.
I'm so sorry.
This is my ringtone.
Bow before Thoraxis.
Okay, seriously,
what was it?
You wear glasses?
You have a back brace?
Say it.
I don't care.
MAN:  And I asked myself
what does space smell like?
You see,
the thing of it...
Oh, hey,
there you guys are.
Oh, this is so nice,
just three friends,
friending around
all unthreatened-like.
Terribly sorry.
This is slightly
embarrassing.
I seem to have
forgotten your name.
It's Troy!
You know it's Troy!
Okay, it's the first part
of  Troy and Abed.
Toby and Abed
in the Morning?
That's ridiculous.
I'm not psycho!
MAN:  Okay.
Where was I?
Oh, yes...
Troy's been
acting weird lately.
The same thing happened
with my constable
when he got a wife.
Which means of course
I now have one spare ticket
to the 50th anniversary
Inspector Spacetime
Convention in London.
Demiceninspecticon?
But it's so soon,
and London's too far.
In England,
Cadbury creme eggs
are sold year-round.
I thought
that was just a legend.
Past life as an alien...
ANNIE: Just a minute.
Just a second.
I've got your hair dryer,
Mrs. Winger.
Oh, thank you, Randy,
but it's not for me.
It's for my husband.
He really needs
the diffuser for his hair.
It sounds shallow,
but he's a lawyer.
Actually,
having dual careers
has put a lot of stress
on our marriage.
Hence the separate rooms.
But I think this trip
is really gonna change
all that.
My husband
will finally see me
not as a world-famous
police detective,
but as a woman.
Your husband's
a lucky man.
That he is.
(COUGHS)
Mmm.
Tastes of bog.
You see? It's funny
because it's clear.
(CHUCKLES)
Actually I would like
to say something.
I am friends with
a couple of huge
Inspector Spacetime fans,
and I think
what they like
about the show
is that it's smart,
complicated,
and doesn't talk down
to its audience.
So, if you'd like to
make a really good
American version,
you should
stay true to that.
Hey, instead
of this constable,
what about a blonde
with long legs
and a tennis racket?
Yes.
Please. For me.
Bow before...
Normally we don't
concern ourselves
with adultery,
'cause then hotels
wouldn't exist.
But everyone here
thinks you're so nice.
So I had to
bring you down here.
I don't believe it.
He told me he was leaving.
Say your catchphrase.
I'd rather not.
What the hell
is going on here?
Suddenly our marriage
isn't worth repairing?
What?
Whoo!
Wait, Nigel is married?
That is so Thoraxis.
And your American accent
isn't at all convincing.
We come all this way,
and you just
leave me alone
without so much as sending
a text message?
I am sick of it, Jeff...
Nigel Winger.
Can I get two more
of these, please?
Enough!
This day has turned crazy.
I'm gonna go upstairs,
towel off,
and pray to God
that I wake up
in the middle of a final
for a class I didn't know
I was enrolled in.
(SCOFFS)
Shoo.
Oh, honey.
You went
all psycho girlfriend
on Abed, didn't you?
Yeah. I screwed up.
Classic Troy.
It's okay.
It happens to
the best of us.
I got you a present.
A quantum spanner.
Yeah, it lights up
or plays music
or something.
Britta, would you agree
to be bonded to me
forever in
the gluon chamber
for an expensive
souvenir photograph?
Absolutely.
(SIGHS)
Thank you.
(SILENTLY) What?
I can't wait.
We can visit
the original
Spacetime set.
And I've got
a spare bedroom,
so you can stay
as long as you like.
That all sounds great.
But I don't know
if I could just
pick up and leave.
I have a life here.
For now.
What do you mean?
Well, let's face it.
Neurotypicals don't have
the same focus you or I have.
They always
get distracted...
By marriage, kids,
competitive cooking shows.
Like your
best friend David.
That's right.
Who was planning
on coming here
even though
you were trapped
in Nigeria?
Yeah, but I wouldn't
say trapped.
And you went to me
and not to your best friend
and constable for help?
Well, his wife
probably deleted
the email.
She's a total...
BOTH: Minerva.
Right.
And you're dressed
as the third Inspector,
who was famous for trying
to strangle the actor
who played
Constable Dudley,
because they were
both pursuing
Linda McCartney.
David doesn't
actually exist, does he?
You're mad.
Nothing you've said
can prove that.
Except that when we met
you said his name
was Andrew.
Bollocks.
Yeah.
All right.
Guilty as charged.
Look, I had to be sure,
didn't I?
When you sent me
that first email
in which you figured out
that Inspector Spacetime
is both his own grandfather
and grandmother,
I knew we were soul mates.
You and I are special.
Neurotypicals won't admit it,
but some people
are just better
than everybody else.
They can't handle it,
so they always leave.
Just like how
the brilliant Inspector
has constant adventures,
while his constables
always eventually return
to their dull, ordinary
Earth lives.
But maybe there's a reason
the Inspector always chooses
a human companion.
He's an alien,
but his human friends
keep him grounded
and invested in the world,
like with me and Troy.
If I could Winger you
for a second.
Sure. I don't know
what that means, but...
Maybe all relationships are
made up of logical inspectors
and emotional constables,
and we need both
to make space and time
a better place.
Maybe you're right.
Wait, wait.
Toby, Toby, Toby, no.
Wait just a second.
(CHUCKLES)
Just playing a game.
(EMITS HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
You have to let me out.
No, not until
Stockholm Syndrome sets in.
How long
do you think that'll be,
a couple of hours?
Would you love me
if I got you a churro?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
JEFF: Annie.
Annie, I...
I'm not sure how much air
there is in here!
And still you talk.
Troy will find me.
Who?
You know who Troy is.
Yeah.
Troy will find me.
Okay, just hold it there.
Okay.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Everything okay?
Everything's fine.
What is a gluon anyway?
Can we stop talking
about Abed?
I'm sorry. I can't.
It doesn't feel right.
It's okay.
I understand.
Go to him.
Are you sure?
I've told you before.
I don't care
about  Inspector Spacetime.
Toby.
Where's Abed?
He's packing.
He said you have a girlfriend
and don't need him anymore.
He's coming with me
to England.
You're lying.
How would you know?
Because Abed's my friend,
and he would
have told me.
And he would have
explained it to me
in very clear terms,
because I get confused
sometimes.
He's in there, isn't he?
(CHUCKLES) No.
Hey, Troy.
Hey, Abed.
Toby, have you ever been
in a fight?
Because I have.
Oh, my God.
He can make a fist.
That would hurt harder
than a slap.
He's in that one.
I know that.
You okay?
I am.
You know,
for the first time
in my long history
of being locked
inside things,
I knew
someone would come.
Still want to take
the gluon photo?
What do you think?
Yes.
Well, I just went upstairs
and saw your room.
Saw the two robes,
the two coffee cups,
one with lipstick,
one without.
And I saw actual hair
that looked a lot like mine
on my side
of the sink,
so I have some questions.
Oh, God.
First one,
is that actually my hair,
and, if so,
did it fall out naturally?
Because if it did,
you need to
tell me right now,
'cause I have
to call science.
Also, what the hell
is going on?
All right, I may
have been play-acting
that we were married,
and then the staff
thought you were cheating,
and I had to save face.
Do I have
to worry about this?
No, I was just daydreaming.
I mean,
I've married you at least
a half a dozen times.
And Troy.
And Zac Efron.
Mostly Zac Efron.
Does Zac get a drink
thrown in his face?
(LAUGHTER)
I don't know.
I guess I was a little hurt
that you ditched me.
I mean,
we are friends, right?
Would it have been
that painful to
hang out together?
Well, I can
tell you one thing
your fantasy got wrong.
If we were married,
you wouldn't find me
flirting with another woman
in a hotel bar.
But there are a lot of things
that you think are fun
that I wouldn't want to do
because I'm...
Older?
Not lame.
Do you want to
hang out now?
Can I buy you a drink?
What do you want?
An appletini.
Oh, God,
don't make me order that.
Please?
(GIGGLES) Appletini.
BRITTA: That is so great.
And I have a surprise
for you guys.
Pow!
Really pushing me here.
He's back.
Do you mind
if we crash this party?
That we already crashed.
Pierce, Shirley,
I'm glad you guys made it.
It was rude of me
not to invite you.
I'm sorry.
Just remember, Abed,
I did my best.
We both did.
You're welcome.
So I guess
we're taking off.
Actually, I'd like to stay
for a little while.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You don't have
to do that for me.
Well, who says
it's just for you?
Guys,
get your phones ready,
because you are only
gonna see this once.
(ALL GASPING)
Bow before Thoraxis.
See, this is why
I don't hang with you folks
on the weekends.
(ROCK MUSIC)
Here we are,
the 1960s,
the greatest,
grooviest period
in the entire history
of the entire universe.
I'm lucky. I get to
visit places like this
because I can travel
through time and space,
but not both at once.
Do you know
why that is, ensign?
Because,
Inspector Spacetime,
our minds would be blown
with the space/time confusion.
That's right.
And now I must sleep
with the sexiest
woman here,
who is also
my grandmother,
or I will cease
to exist.
How do you know
I'm not your grandmother?
There's only one way
to find out.
I hate you.