Look, 12:00.
The History of Ice Cream
class is letting out.
It's as informative
as it is delicious!
That class
should've been ours.
I hear the final
is a sundae bar.
Mmm.
TROY: I don't get history.
If I wanted to know
what happened in Europe
a long time ago,
I'd watch  Game of Thrones.
Troy,
that show takes place
in a fantasy realm.
This class is
about the real world.
(GASPS)
Not the show.
You need to think
before you speak.
I heard this teacher's
a real hard-ass.
He's British,
and he has a degree.
I can't have
a hard-buns teacher.
I'm already starting
a new business.
When am I supposed
to see my family?
And last week,
Ben took his first steps
without me.
Quick impression.
"Wah."
Who am I?
You guys.
Ha! Dead on.
I know the
History of Ice Cream
would have been fun,
but not only
will this class
be much less likely
to give us Type 2 Diabetes.
We might actually learn...
Son of a bitch!
(MIMICING TECHNO TUNE)
SHIRLEY: Those annoying
Germans are back?
I thought they
transferred after they lost
their foosball scholarship.
I heard
they were juicing.
No, them leaving
would mean
Greendale got
slightly better,
which, as we know,
does not happen.
Lukas, Karl,
I see you've grown
a new douche bag.
My name is Reinhold.
I believe you know
my brother Juergen.
There was some bad blood
between you two,  ja?
(CHUCKLES)
Don't worry.
If there is one thing
Germans don't do,
it's hold a grudge.
Unless we're talking
about  Die Hard 3.
Or the 20th century.
Morning, everyone.
MAN: Morning.
I am Professor Cornwallis.
I know what
you're all thinking,
and the answer is...
Yes. I am
a direct descendant
of General Sir
Charles Cornwallis,
who surrendered
the British forces
at Yorktown.
Was anyone thinking that?
ALL: No.
History is written
by the victors.
Well, of course,
we all know the quote.
What does it mean?
According to
Oxford University,
it means
that my 20 years'
loyal service there
means nothing
next to a little
slipup with a co-ed.
(CLEARS THROAT)
But what it really means
is that history
can be seen
from a multitude
of vantage points.
So, for your
first test on Monday...
(ALL GROANING)
I'm confused.
When do we
get our ice cream?
I want to challenge you
to look at history
from all perspectives.
How would the story read
if it was written
not by the victors,
but by the vanquished?
Ja.
How indeed?
(CHUCKLES WICKEDLY)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
I was recalling
a very funny episode
of the German version
of  The Nanny.
Franlein gets a...
It wouldn't translate.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one,
They all just fade away ♪
And I still
have those pants.
True story.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, we have fun.
(HIGH-PITCHED SCREAM)
Sorry.
I should've realized
that might be startling.
Dr. Ken Kedan,
Greater Greendale
Mental Health Services.
Kevin, does this gentleman
look familiar to you?
I'm sorry.
He doesn't.
Kevin? Uh-uh.
His name is Chang.
Oh, of course.
That explains the note.
"Hello, my name is Kevin.
I have Changnesia"?
What is that?
It's not uncommon
for victims of memory loss
to experience some
syntactical confusion.
Thus the inappropriate
insertion of his name
into an unrelated phrase.
No, he's always Dean that.
Once we learned of the
connection to Greendale,
we realized it would be
the perfect environment
for some immersive therapy.
What?
No, absolutely not!
I can't have
an unbalanced nut job
traipsing around
on my campus!
Put that on the rack.
Put that in the fridge.
Get him out of here!
Sorry.
Your school board
already signed off on it.
Kevin is now
your responsibility.
(HIGH-PITCHED WAIL)
I just felt
a strange disturbance.
Did you have dairy
this morning?
Could be that.
Or it could be that
great evil is nearby.
I'll take
a provisional lactaid.
Won't be needing
the lactaid.
Uh, guys?
This is our study room.
Please leave, and take
that mushroom cloud
of Drakkar with you.
Why must he hurt so
with his words?
He's like
a less funny
Hans Rickles.
I'm not here to argue,
Angela Jerk-els. Beat it!
Ohhh!
Someone must have
changed the channel to USA,
'cause I just watched
a  Burn Notice.
Oh.
Who's Angela Jerk-els?
I can assure you,
we are here for no reason
other than to study.
Our usual
off-campus haunt,
Der Kaffee Hausen,
is closed for the shooting
of an esoteric art film.
Tomorrow it shall re-open,
unt we shall be
out of your heavily
product-laden hair.
(CHUCKLES)
Jeff, it's just
a little table in the
corner of the room.
Why don't we just
let them have it?
Because that's
called appeasement.
And everyone knows
if you give the Germans
something small,
like the study room
or Austria,
they end up
wanting something big,
like Earth.
Oh.
PIERCE: Jeff's right.
If there were more people
in the world like Annie,
we'd all be speaking
Vietnamese right now.
(GASPS IN SHOCK)
That was my war.
I had flashbacks
for years.
Pierce,
you moved to Canada.
And it was hell.
Those people
call ham "bacon".
This is silly.
I'm just gonna
walk over there
and tell them
they are welcome
to share our room.
Delightful.
So today,
we study in here.
Unt tonight,
we dine in hell.
(BEAT-BOXING TECHNO BEAT)
(ALL IMITATING TECHNO TUNE)
Doktor Blitz,
Knight of the Atlantis Guild,
wielder of the four-pronged
trident on SpawnCraft?
How did you know?
I recognized your catchphrase,
"Tonight we dine in hell!"
I'm spacetimer8032.
You are spacetimer8032?
The one and only.
It's wonderful to
meet you. Brother.
What was that all about?
You two seemed
pretty chummy.
That man saved my life.
In a video game.
Let me get this as straight
as I can get things.
You authorized this?
After everything
that happened last year?
Hear us out.
They offered money.
Did it ever occur
to you that this man
is a psychopath
who may be faking
his own Changnesia?
Oh, now he
has me saying it.
Amdeansia.
Amdeansia...
I'm all turned around.
If he is faking,
you're welcome to prove it.
We get the money
either way.
Mmm!
Oh, I will prove it.
And I'll have fun
doing it.
Now, what to wear?
See?
I know those guys
were annoying yesterday,
but aren't you glad
we didn't turn it
into a whole big
macho war thing?
Gosh, Annie,
you're right.
I can't believe
I doubted you.
Hey, apropos of nothing,
what's that sound
you make when you
see something shocking?
(GASPS IN SHOCK)
Oh, yeah, that's it.
What are you guys
doing at our table?
What happened
to Der Kaffee Hausen?
Our time in
this room yesterday
proved more pleasant
than expected.
It's got a good energy.
That table is ours.
This room is ours!
You guys need to leave.
Hey, Karl.
Hi, Abed.
I am afraid
it is you who must do
the making like a tree,
which is to say, leaving.
Uh, security!
You want us to leave?
There a problem here?
Yeah, there's a problem.
These dussle-dorks
won't leave our study room.
Nice!
I don't understand
any of these puns.
I think I need
to learn history.
Do you have
a sign-in sheet?
You're asking
for our papers?
I thought
this was America,
not Arizona.
We have a sign-in sheet.
Lukas.
Perhaps we should
all just go home
and see our families
and think things
through, huh?
Looks like
the room is theirs.
(CHUCKLES)
Shirley,
call your babysitter,
because this means...
Let me guess.
War?
Let the lady finish
her sentence.
Thank you, Jeff!
War. Yeah.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
We'd like to sign out
study room "F".
It would appear
that in this battle,
our bulge was
a little bit bigger.
(CHUCKLES)
Guten bye-bye.
Excuse me.
Don't touch.
Damn them
and their perfectly
crafted timepieces.
What else
do you have available?
(SIGHS)
(LIGHT BUZZING)
It's like
a Darren Aronofsky film.
I'll get this.
My fifth father-in-law
was an electrician.
You pick up
a thing or two.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Agh! Everybody grab me,
please! Ugh!
Nobody grab him.
(SCREAMING)
Pierce, just let go.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Of the thing, Pierce.
Oh, it smells
like barbecue.
We're getting up
earlier tomorrow.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(EVIL LAUGHTER)
(AIR HISSING)
Oh, no.
Oh!
Ugh!
(SOMBER MUSIC)
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
Oh, look at them!
(SOBBING)
(SAD MUSIC)
(CRASH)
Hi.
Thanks again
for taking me in.
We must have been great pals
before my Changnesia, huh?
Oh, my...
That's it.
You may have fooled
that handsome doctor,
but you can't fool me.
Oh, how convenient.
Showing up here
with Changnesia
after you staged a coup,
almost blew up the school,
and locked me in
a basement for months!
Without so much as
a drop of moisturizer!
I did all that?
I mean,
Chang did all that?
If that's true,
then Chang,
who is me,
deserves to go to jail.
Well, he did.
And you do.
This is the worst thing
that's happened to me
in my 96 hours
of memory.
(DOOR OPENS)
And that failed
ventriloquist's name
was Slobodan Milosevic.
ALL: Ohh.
For the essay portion
of your test on Monday,
you will be
asked to describe
a historical battle
from the perspectives
of both the winners
and the losers.
No dioramas.
(ALL GROANING)
Guten luck
on the examination.
We will be preparing for it
in study room "F",
as in "fictory".
I like the way
your old chair
cradles  mein knaidels.
(LAUGHTER)
I just made that up.
You know, English
is my second language.
Jeff, stop.
It's over.
No.
These guys are horrible.
Totally. Except Karl.
Really, Abed?
Mmm-hmm.
Karl's not horrible?
Even though he took
your home?
When I was growing up,
it was just me and my mom.
I didn't have
much of a family.
That is,
until I met you guys.
So excuse me
if I'm not willing
to give up
the place where
we became a family.
So what are we gonna do?
We literally can't
get up any earlier.
Many years ago,
before the concept
of "too soon" existed,
there was a show about
a bunch of goofy Nazis
running a prison camp,
and that show was called...
Hogan's Heroes?
Hogan's Heroes.
Yes.
And while,
for a latchkey kid
with no Jewish friends,
it was a bit desensitizing,
it still taught me
that the lovable misfits
always win.
And the bumbling Germans
always lose.
All we need
is a clever ruse.
Strike that.
All we need is a ruse.
You had me at "ruse."
That was the
last thing I said.
Good thing you said it.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(LIVELY GERMAN MUSIC)
Ah!
Welcome to Oktoberfest.
What is this?
Call it a peace offering.
You won.
We lost.
Let's end this dumb war
and move on.
Care for some
authentic blutwurst?
This stuff's the real deal.
We got it
down in little Munich.
(WHISPERS) It's been
banned by the FDA.
Ooh!
No, Karl!
That blutwurst was
probably injected
with a laxative to make
us pull a Grete Waitz
in our trousers.
I promise you,
there's nothing gross
in this sausage.
It's just pig's blood stuffed
into a cow's intestine.
Gott, that must be
nearly 100  luftballons!
(LAUGHING)
Idiot!
Do not accept
their gifts.
Something is clearly up.
Please, these are
just small tokens
of our friendship.
Oh, come on.
Dirndls, blutwurst,
luftballons.
A cartoonishly large cake.
This is a ruse.
It is exactly
like an episode
of Hogan's Villains.
Ruse?
This is no ruse.
Just take that large cake
back to the study room
and enjoy it there.
So there's nothing hiding
inside this giant
German chocolate cake?
Ask Abed.
You can trust him.
He's a friend.
Nope. Just solid cake.
Hmm.
Then you wouldn't mind
if I...
Cut the cake?
Or you could
save it for later.
You don't have to share it.
Shirley stayed up all night
baking that for you.
No problem.
I just used the eggs
I would've used
for my son's breakfast.
But it would be
so easy for me
to carve into this cake.
And serve us all!
Wait!
Damn it. Sorry.
We thought you were
stupider than this.
Troy.
Should I release the tear gas,
or has that ship sank?
(CHUCKLES)
An excellent attempt, Winger,
but we are smarter than you,
and once again,
it shall be us
who are savoring
the smooth and somewhat
ha-ha-hoppy taste of victory.
Beer me,  bitte.
Here you go.
As they say
in  Ferris Bueller,
danke schoen.
And as they say
in the movie,  Gotcha...
Gotcha.
Busted.
Busted?
For what?
But there were
dozens of students
at that Oktoberfest.
But you were the only
German students
celebrating German culture,
and here at Greendale,
that is a big, fat no-no.
We frown on anyone celebrating
their own cultural heritage.
I mean, if the Hasidic
student union wants
to host a kwanzaa celebration,
you go, Jews!
Hanukkah? No, sir.
It's why I keep
a detailed list
of every student's race
and nationality
to prevent racism
and nationalism.
This is an outrage!
Relax.
It's not like
you're expelled.
You're just
banned from certain
campus amenities,
uh, water fountains,
swimming pools... Huh.
Most of these
are water-based.
Oh, and the study rooms.
Oh!
Uh!
(PHONE RINGS)
Oh, I gotta take this.
Bye-bye.
Dean Pelton,
if I don't offer
you a receipt,
your education is free.
Chang did what?
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Oh, cool.
What are we protesting?
WOMAN: You guys.
You've been hogging that
study room for three years.
Somebody finally
stood up to you,
and you had them banned.
Why must our people
always be the victims?
What do we want?
ALL: Justice!
When do we want it?
Now!
What do we want?
Justice!
Oh, my God.
When do we want it?
Now!
This whole time,
we thought the Germans
were the Germans.
But it turns out,
we're the Germans.
Hang on.
You guys are all siding
with the Germans?
You realize
these guys are, like,
contractor-grade tools.
They signed out that room
fair and square,
and then you
had to take it too far,
like you always do
with that room.
Yeah!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(SIGHS)
Damn it!
I signed this room out!
And I have
a final tomorrow!
They lost a pen.
Can you come back
in a few hours?
We're playing
Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
Yes?
I left my notebook in there.
Well, you're going to have
to come back later.
I'm trying to prove a point.
You're like those guys
on  Hogan's Heroes.
The Nazis.
(GASPS)
You take that back!
I'm Jewish.
Yeah, Leonard.
Don't call me a Nazi.
You are wearing
an SS T-shirt.
Oh.
Oh!
(KEYS JINGLE)
Open two.
(DOOR LOCK BUZZES)
What are you doing here?
You, sir,
have been bailed out.
We are going to nurse you
back to health.
But why?
Why take me back in
after everything
I did to you?
When I heard
that you had checked
yourself into jail,
I realized
you couldn't be faking.
The real Chang
would never have remorse
for what he did.
I believe you...
Kevin.
Plus, curing Changnesia,
that's a human interest story.
That puts Greendale
on the map.
But your health
comes second, whoop, first,
to the school.
Oh, let's not hug.
Do you mind getting my...
Okay.
Probably shouldn't
step on it.
I feel guilty
eating this cake.
And not for
the usual reasons.
Hate to say it,
but this is what happens
when a group of people
blindly follows
a charismatic,
golden-throated leader.
Are you actually
comparing me to Hitler?
(OVERLAPPING AGREEMENTS)
There are similarities.
Hang on.
Nobody's even willing
to consider that I might be
the Hitler of this group?
We were the good guys.
How could everybody think
we're the bad guys?
We are.
When Karl and I were raiding
the diamond north caves,
I was facing
50 death beatles.
I would've perished for sure,
but he saved me.
Then when I had a chance
to return the favor,
I looked him in the eye,
and I told him
it was solid cake.
You were just
following orders.
There's probably a way
I can make it up to him.
Oh.
Maybe I'll give him
my four-pronged trident.
Why don't you call it
a "quadrident"?
Shh.
Ah!
There you people are.
I believe we have
something to discuss.
Oh, my God.
You clever British bastard.
You set this whole thing up
to teach us a lesson.
What?
Making the school pretend
to hate us,
to show us that
one man's hero
is another man's villain.
Of course!
We aren't Nazis.
(LAUGHTER)
I tip my cap
to you, sir.
Lesson learned.
Are you actually suggesting
that a professor
at Greendale
would set up
an elaborate ruse
just to teach
seven students a lesson?
Uh, yes.
Yeah.
Yes.
That's a Wednesday.
Oh, my God.
I've made a terrible
mistake coming here.
So this wasn't
part of the class?
Then why are you here?
Because you had
a test today,
and you all missed it!
"F"s FOR EVERYONE.
Oh.
Maybe it's not too late
to get out
of my contract.
I really am Hitler.
Yeah.
So it's just decided.
No vote or anything.
I hate this.
I wish there was
a way that we could
make it up to people.
That's it.
We need to make reparations.
We have to start
giving back
because Greendale
has given us so much.
It gave us
the study room.
And that study room
is our home.
But our home is more
than those four walls.
And our family is more
than the seven of us.
It's all of Greendale.
And everyone deserves
to have what we have.
What do you know?
Greendale just got
slightly better.
It's good to be back.
Should we go celebrate
at Skeeper's?
Oh, come on, Shirley.
We all have lives.
There you are!
I am so proud
how you stepped up
and made amends.
And everyone forgave you.
Because when it comes
right down to it,
Greendale's
a forgiving place.
It really is.
Please keep that in mind
the next 20 seconds.
Remember that people
can "Chang".
People can what?
Hmm?
Hi, I'm Kevin.
(ALL SCREAMING)
He has Changnesia.
(TROY AND ABED HUMMING)
And you know
what that sound is.
BOTH: It's the
Troy and Abed Podcast.
Sponsored by
Shirley's sandwiches,
home of the
fried chicken skin wrap.
Is it inside?
Is it outside?
You find out.
Okay, our guest today
is from Germany, Europe.
Karl,  guten tag.
How are you doing?
Sehr gut.
Great.
Now's the part of the show
where we get real.
Friendship, loyalty,
betrayal, redemption.
Is this an apology?
Yes.
And for being a guest
on the show today,
we want you to have this.
It's a gift certificate
to Shirley's sandwiches,
home of the
triple-fried Monte Cristo.
We challenge you
to taste the bread.
This coupon is a $5 bill.
Well, that's all the time
we have today.
For Troy Barnes,
I'm Abed Nadir.
And for Abed Nadir,
I'm Troy Barnes.
BOTH: And we're out.
Thanks so much
for doing this.
So will you be on
my podcast tomorrow?
We've got a thing.
Beep, boop, bow!
(SMOOTH JAZZ PLAYING)