Well, see you
after the break.
What are you all doing
for Thanksgiving?
I'm having Andre's
whole family over,
though he'll be stuck
working at the stereo
store for Black Friday.
Oh, sure,
you get to say that,
but we're stuck
calling it "Jew Friday."
Ugh,
I'll be with my family,
fielding the same
old questions.
"How's community college?"
"What's your major?"
"Are those real?"
(GASPS)
My aunt's boyfriend.
"Oh, my family's
a normal religion,
"so I have to talk
to them for five minutes
"before I get a casserole
that's all marshmallow."
That's you.
Uh, a brainstorm.
Why don't you all
come over to my house?
I'll have plenty of food.
That would be great.
Sounds good to me.
(HOOTS) Marshmallows.
I was going to microwave
buttered noodles,
but this sounds
equally promising.
I'm in.
Oh, goody. Well,
you know, you're all
welcome, of course.
I'm in.
Or, you know,
Jeff or whoever.
Can't. Plans.
Well,
if you change your mind,
I can't think of anyone
who would enjoy
having you more.
How-dean, pilgrims.
Is that...
John Wayne, yes.
Oh, good, you got it.
Anyhoo, I just thought
I'd mosey on over here,
invite you all
to Greendale's
Annual Thanks-living
potluck dinner,
where we remember
all we have to be
thankful for.
There may be
a statistical link
to enrollment
at Greendale
and holiday suicide.
Oh.
Just a shoelace,
and belt-free night
full of fun.
You should all drop by.
Or Jeff. Or whoever.
Oh, he can't.
He has plans.
Oh, right,
you are spending
Thanksgiving
with your father.
(ALL GASP)
I thought I told you
to stop reading my email.
Yeah, well,
I thought I told you
to stop keeping secrets.
How am I supposed
to keep track of what
you tell me in confidence
and what I hear
through your walls
with a glass to my ear?
Fine.
Close your mouths.
I'm having Thanksgiving
with my estranged father.
Can we move on now?
Makes sense.
Jeff's at a point in his life
where he needs a strong
father figure to come out to.
Jeff,
this is huge news.
Huger news.
Was this decision
made after our
Halloween conversation?
Yes, after.
Not because of.
I'll take it.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
You had that teed up?
♪ When I say "thera,"
you say "pist"
♪ Thera
♪ Pist
♪ Thera... ♪
(ALL GROANING)
Thanks for the support,
guys.
Oh, the support
has just begun.
What do you want me
to bring to Papa Winger's
house,
some vegan pumpkin pie?
Britta,
you're not coming.
Fine,
regular pumpkin pie.
Jeff, you're going
to need me
when things get
messy and emotional.
The only thing
that's going to get messy
and emotional is Troy,
when he realizes
there are yams underneath
those marshmallows.
I knew it was too good
to be true.
Jeff, speaking not
just as your friend
but as an avid
daytime TV watcher,
these parent-child reunions
can get intense.
Chairs might be thrown.
Weaves might be pulled.
Or I could just go in there,
show him how awesome I am,
no thanks to him,
meet my half-brother...
(ALL GASPING)
And then, boom.
Closure.
Your dad
has another son?
Yeah.
So, clearly,
he's moved on.
Why can't I?
Close your mouths.
Look, I appreciate
your concern,
but really,
the most helpful
thing you can do
is stay out of my business.
Oh, can you say
that last part again?
(SIGHS) These walls
are entirely too thick.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
Ha.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Oh!
Happy Thanksgiving,
everyone.
Hey.
Hi.
Let's carve
that jive turkey!
Got that out
of your system?
Yeah.
Then I'm so happy
to welcome you all
to my home.
Oh, thank you.
Hello, come in.
(GIGGLES)
Take your coats off.
Make yourself comfortable.
Browse the available
literature about Jesus Christ
as your personal savior.
Or not.
No agenda.
Are you going
to pass some apps soon,
or do I have to die
of starvation to prove
a point?
Oh, everybody,
this is Mr. Bennett,
my father-in-law.
Dad, these are my friends
from college.
(FARTS)
Oh, yeah.
That's Andre's people.
They're a bunch of characters.
That's a good one, dad.
Oh, I brought
something.
Oh.
Dip.
Oh, Abed, why is this
seven layer dip so puffy?
Oh, it's been
in the fridge
for two years.
I was saving it
for a special occasion.
Oh, that's so thoughtful.
I'm going to put this
on a nice platter
with some crackers
in the trash.
Where's Britta?
BRITTA:
Hey, Jeff. What's up?
What's up is closure.
I met my dad,
we talked things out as men.
I think I'm ready
to move on.
Really, in 20 minutes?
Fine.
Look, I couldn't do it.
I was at the front door,
totally in control,
and then I started thinking
about all that stuff you said
about messiness,
and it threw me off my game.
You know,
the irony is,
after all your pestering that
I deal with my daddy issues,
you're the reason
I'm not meeting my father.
Or maybe I'm the reason
you'll come here after all.
Britta, I...
Wait.
What do you mean by "here"?
Your dad's house,
where I kind of,
sort of, am.
Yeah, thanks, Sharon.
I never thought
about it that way.
Batman is sort of gay.
Be right back.
What is going on?
Why is Thanksgiving
so terrible?
I know.
The tension, the backbiting,
the judgmental comments.
This makes Thanksgiving
with my family look...
Eh, still pretty bad.
I said Batman was gay.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SCOFFS)
Sheesh.
You ask one lady
if she's Tyler Perry in drag,
and suddenly,
you're the bad guy.
It's a reference.
That's my humor.
Abed gets it.
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh, you're all
hiding out in here.
We're not hiding.
You know us,
hide away.
Well, be careful.
You might be giving
the impression that you
prefer the cold garage
to the warm heart
of my hospitality.
What? As if.
Yay.
Uh-huh. Okay.
Well, hurry back soon.
(GIGGLES)
This is the Jonestown
of dinners.
I feel like I'm in jail.
And you know what happens
to guys like me in jail.
They get really
into push-ups,
and I am fine
with my upper body
the way it is!
(SIGHS)
ABED:
It did feel like a prison,
and that meant only one thing
made sense, conceptually.
We had to break out.
And someone
with the gravitas
of Morgan Freeman
had to narrate it.
We need to do
a prison break.
(SIGHS)
Happy Thanksgiving?
You really "you'd"
this one, huh?
Okay, yes, I meddled
against your wishes,
and yes,
I got this address
from the Dean, but hey.
You had a moment of doubt,
and here I am to help you
through it.
Psychology tells us
there are no accidents.
Oh, really?
What about car accidents,
Tara Reid,
or the Hindenburg?
Here goes nothing.
Hello, William.
So, uh, how about we make
a couple of ground rules?
Actually,
that sounds good.
Okay.
No hugs.
Wouldn't want one.
No apologies.
Wouldn't accept one.
No calling you "Dad."
No expectations.
No BS.
Drink?
Scotch.
Eighteen?
Neat.
I just want to acknowledge
that there are
a lot of emotions
flowing right now,
and you two are probably
feeling a strong impulse
to sleep with each other,
and hey, that's normal.
Wow.
I'll get the drinks.
So, how about that?
No muss, no fuss.
Jeff, I urge you not to run
from the muss and fuss.
Hi.
You must be
my half-brother.
Oh, your hands
are so much bigger
than mine.
Your nail beds are perfect.
I can't do it.
I can't.
Oh, God.
Oh, it's coming up.
When I get upset,
I vomit.
Oh, I see you've
met Willy Junior.
You said he wasn't
going to replace me.
He's the Schwarzenegger.
I'm the DeVito.
I get it.
(LAUGHS)
Okay, fellas,
let's get right into it.
I think the big question
on everyone's mind is,
why don't I go
help Willy Junior?
Hmm?
ABED:
One thing was clear to me
and the rest of the crew.
Bennett lockup was not
where we belonged.
We belonged in the sun,
with the wind in our hair,
or maybe at a Bennigan's,
enjoying a Turkey O'Toole.
We should tunnel out.
Abed,
Shirley is our friend,
and we're guests
in her home.
We need a plan
that won't hurt
her feelings,
or damage her property.
Definitely don't look
behind that poster, then.
I could pretend
to have a stroke.
Do a gibberish
foreign language.
What if I did
a gibberish foreign
language like  Star Wars?
You'd like that, I bet.
Dick.
Look, I'm sure
we'll figure out
a way out of here.
What's important
right now is that
we stick together.
Yeah.
Oh, there you are.
Who wants
a pre-dinner snack?
(GROANS)
Oh!
Oh, pumpkin,
what's wrong?
Oh, it's too embarrassing
to talk about in front
of the guys, know what
I mean, girlfriend?
Oh, sweetie.
Do you have
your monthly shame?
SHIRLEY:
Do you want to lie down
in Elijah's room?
Oh, I don't think
that's going to cut it.
I probably need to go home
and call Dr. Collins.
It's that bad.
Oh, well, you know,
my sister-in-law's
a gynecologist,
and she's right
in the other room.
There's no need to bother
your doctor on a holiday.
Go ahead.
Mmm-hmm.
ABED:  I'd like to tell you
Annie avoided Shirley's
doctor sister-in-law,
but this ain't no fairy tale.
This is Thanksgiving.
WILLIAM:
Let's see, what else?
You've got some diabetes,
on my mother's side.
Good to know.
I like your hair.
The presence of it,
I mean.
So I have a question,
and it's been weighing
on me pretty heavily.
At your age,
in the bedroom...
Oh, yeah.
It's all good.
Yeah?
Real good.
Look at them.
Bonding.
Probably laughing
'cause I can't grow a beard.
(SNAP FINGERS)
I have an idea.
Why don't we use
these dinner rolls
to do some "roll" play?
(CHUCKLES)
I see what I did there.
Okay.
This roll,
this is me.
He's crying.
Good.
That's really good.
So, uh,
what do you do?
I'm a lawyer who faked
a Bachelor's degree
and practiced Law
for seven years
before I got caught.
(LAUGHS)
I like your hustle.
Reminds me of the summer
I was Ralph Lauren
out in St. Tropez.
'83, I'm on a boat
with, uh...
Damn it, Willy!
I'm expressing.
Knock it off.
Why can't you just
swallow it, like any
normal person?
Oh! Oh, right.
Like your new son.
Like Mister... (STAMMERS)
Mister I've Got My Shirt...
I don't know a lot
of personal details
about you yet.
Well, my name's Jeff.
Don't help me,
Mr. Helper Guy.
First mom dies,
now this?
Hey, she died
20 years ago, Willy.
He keeps singing
the same old song.
Wow.
She died on you.
Here I thought
you'd become
Father of the Year,
but you just got stuck.
Yeah, well, look,
I don't have to tell you
I'm not a natural caretaker,
but with Willy,
you know, I...
I checked all the boxes,
and he still turned out
softer than wet cheese.
I don't get it.
He keeps saying
he's going to move out
next week, since '03.
Oh, man, I couldn't
wait to get out.
I got my own place
when I was 18.
I was the same way.
(CHUCKLES)
So who's ready to eat?
Jeff, you care
to carve the turkey?
I knew it!
You love him
more than me.
I'll show you.
I'll run away.
Oh, please.
Hey, be my guest.
You run away,
and I'm going to sleep
like a baby tonight.
(WHIMPERS)
Oh, now, I'm sorry
you guys had to see that,
but maybe you could
shrink his head,
since you're here
for some reason.
Yes.
I can do this.
Show me on the dinner roll
where you're hurt!
ABED:
And that's how it went
for the afternoon.
This tag team turkey day
became our routine.
We endured the indignities
as best we could.
Cousins fighting,
complaints about the food,
listening to a nephew
do Borat for a full hour.
We figured out
ways to steal away
from time to time,
saying we had to pee,
had to get ice,
had to do a Jewish thing
in the other room.
(HARMONICA PLAYING)
I became known as the guy
who could get you things
piece of gum,
playing cards,
some novelty glasses
I found in a box
marked "crap."
In those brief,
tranquil moments,
we felt human.
We felt free.
But sooner or later,
our warden would
come knocking.
Mostly, we just waited
for our time to be served,
but some didn't take
kindly to waiting.
Some didn't have
much time left.
Enough.
Amateur hour is over.
I'm going in there,
pretend to break a hip,
and we'll be sipping
Sambuca at Skeepers
in no time.
(FAINT COMMOTION)
Whoa.
He tripped on the rug.
Wait,
now he's getting up.
He's walking around dazed
like he's got a head injury.
Oh, groin into
the corner of the table.
This might actually work.
PIERCE: Ow!
(LAUGHTER)
Wait, wait,
why are people laughing?
(GRUNTS)
Let's see, I need a broom,
a rake, or two rakes...
Pierce, you were supposed
to pretend to injure
yourself so we could leave.
Leave?
This is my
Showtime at the Apollo.
I'm killing out there.
(GUESTS CHEERING)
ABED:
Pierce was our last hope,
or so we thought.
It seemed Troy Barnes
had a plan.
What if we got sick?
No.
No more faking illnesses.
Not fake sick.
Real sick.
And that's when I told
my old firm to shove it.
(CHUCKLES)
I've always been more
of a free agent, anyway.
Yeah, I can see
that about you.
You seem like
a self-made man.
Well, I kind of had to be.
Look, if it's okay with you,
I'd like to break a rule.
I know we said
"no mushy stuff,"
but for what it's worth,
I'm proud of you.
Wow. Thanks.
Makes you think.
Wait, what do you mean?
Well, look, I mean,
you've seen how
Willy turned out.
I mean, I haven't
done that kid any favors.
And so I look at you,
so self-reliant
and well-adjusted,
and I think maybe
I did something right.
You did something right?
Well, let me say
that different.
Uh, the universe
is a constantly expanding...
Stop.
I get the impulse,
but that's not going
to work here.
No, I just mean
that, uh,
we are defined
by what happens to us,
and me leaving
seems to have made
you independent,
made you strong.
With all due respect,
which is none,
go to hell.
So tunneling out
is off the table?
(DOOR OPENS)
Who's hungry
for turkey?
Shirley,
we were just...
About to...
Eat garbage dip.
Why did I have
to go third?
Look, I get it.
You want to leave.
Shirley, we're sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
To be honest,
I invited you
as a bit of a buffer.
With Andre's family,
I'm always the butt
of the joke,
and with Andre
gone this year,
I thought I could
tip the scales in my favor
by having
a few friends around.
That was wrong of me.
See you Monday.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I can't believe
none of us noticed
she was having
such a hard time.
ANNIE: We can't leave.
ABED:
Funny thing about prison.
Sometimes the person
you thought was your warden
turns out to be
a fellow prisoner,
which doesn't really
line up with the whole
Shawshank  thing,
but maybe we've
always been doing
more of a Prison Break.
The show.
Whoa, what are
you doing in my car?
Take me with you.
Teach me what you know.
What in the cat's cradle
is happening?
Dad hates me.
What do you care
what that guy thinks?
He's a dick.
See, that's what
I need to learn!
How to be all dead inside
with muscles on top,
not all emotional and flabby.
Yeah,
but you are emotional,
and if you pretend
you're not, you're only
letting him off the hook
for being a terrible father,
which he is
and always has been.
I mean,
he meant the world to you,
and you meant
nothing to him,
and if you run away now,
he'll never know.
He should know.
Britta's the worst.
Ow! Jeez.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Oh.
I thought you guys left.
We started
as your buffer,
but we're busting you
out of here now.
Mmm-hmm.
I drew a map
of your house
on my stomach.
Uh, I know what
my house looks like.
That's what I said.
Look, if we act fast,
we can get through
this plan,
which is to put
you in the trash can,
take you out like trash,
but we got to dress
you like a baby.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
Thank you so much for
doing this, but I'm not
going anywhere.
Those people up there,
they may be rude,
they may be pushy,
they may have come
to some wrongheaded
conclusions
about Batman and Robin...
Oh, thank you.
But they're my family,
and family means
putting up with each other
even when it's hard.
You guys can go.
I'll be fine.
Actually,
we're going to stay.
Oh.
Yeah.
Family sticks it out.
(DOOR OPENS)
That's ni...
Okay, full disclosure.
We're hiding out
from that crazy white guy.
You came back!
I'm sorry.
You should
take some credit
for who I've become.
Okay.
So, let me tell you
how I turned out,
just so you're
crystal clear
on your impact.
I am not well-adjusted.
More often than not,
I am barely
keeping it together.
I'm constantly texting,
and there's no one
at the other end.
I'm just a grown man
who can't even
look his own friends
in the eye for too long
because I'm afraid
that they'll see
that I am broken.
So you get
credit for that.
Oh, come on, now...
One time,
when I was in seventh grade,
I told everybody at school
that I had appendicitis.
I wanted someone
to worry about me.
But when Beth Brannon
asked to see the scar,
I didn't want
to get found out,
so I took mom's scissors,
and I made one.
It hurt like hell,
but it was worth it.
Because I got 17 cards,
and I still keep
them in a box
underneath my bed,
22 years later,
because it proves
that someone,
at some point,
cared about me.
You want to see the scar?
So you get credit
for that, too.
This is me.
Look, Jeff,
I, uh...
(SHOUTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Daddy!
Are you faking
a heart attack?
Kind of a Hail Mary.
(SIGHS)
Happy Thanksgiving, Dad.
Look, you're probably
feeling a very strong urge
to sleep with me right now,
and that is normal.
(SARCASTICALLY) Sure.
Britta, thank you.
You were right.
You're not going to get all
Jock Jams on me, are you?
No, of course not.
I left my boom box
at school.
(KNOCKING ON WINDOW)
Oh.
Jeez.
You got to stop
doing that.
Thank you.
Come here, brother.
Oh.
JEFF: Wow.
JEFF: Why don't you
save some for Christmas,
buddy, okay?
And then Pierce
did whiteface
over blackface.
No one was amused.
It's meta.
Abed gets it.
So, Troy,
how was your first
real Thanksgiving?
No offense to Shirley,
but I don't see
what the fuss is about.
Thanksgiving's the wors...
WOMEN: Oh!
I heard your Thanksgiving
wasn't much better than mine,
so I thought
we could take some time
and be grateful
for our real family.
The one we chose.
So pretty.
JEFF: Sit, sit, sit.
ABED:  We never got
to do a Shawshank  homage,
not the way I wanted to.
Maybe the hardest prisons
to break out of
are the ones without locks.
Wait, that doesn't
make any sense.
After that day,
Jeff seemed like
a man unburdened.
He told me about
seeing his father again,
about how leaving there
felt like breaking free
of an emotional prison
he'd been in for years.
Something about
shackles on his heart?
To be honest,
I stopped listening.
I was thinking
about Christmas.
I hope we do Die Hard.
I hope it's in a restaurant.
I hope it lays out as cleanly
as it does in my dreams.
I hope it's cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
Cheers.
Happy Thanksgiving, everyone,
including you, Dean.
(HUMMING JAZZY TUNE)
Hey.
(HUMMING)
Hmm.
Oh, my.
I'll have to remember
this for next year.
Mmm-hmm.