(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
My name is Kevin,
or so they tell me.
Actually, they told me
my birth name
is Benjamin Chang,
but I can't remember anything
before six months ago.
But by using
a special, shiny glass
called a mirror,
I've estimated
that I'm 15 years old,
although I have no way
of knowing.
Changnesia is a fascinating
and extremely rare disease
on the forefront
of the psychological
landscape.
DR. KEDAN:  Compared with your
garden variety amnesia,
Changnesia is immeasurably
more complex.
Its varied
and seemingly
random symptoms,
its resistance
to both traditional
and new age medicine,
why Changnesia
affects the memory
but not the ability
to make forced puns...
These are all things
we can study
now that someone
finally has it.
I first met Chang
when I hired him
as a Spanish teacher
at Greendale.
Then he became
a disgraced student,
psychopathic music major,
homeless vent dweller,
security guard,
keytarist,
power hungry warlord,
and now, Kevin.
It's sad
to see him like this.
Well, it's mixed.
He was pretty terrible
before.
I'm developing a theory
which some find controversial.
Perhaps Chang
actually used to be Kevin,
went crazy,
and became Chang.
And then,
at some point,
Chang hit his head,
went un-crazy,
thereby reverting back
to regular old Kevin again.
DR. KEDAN:
That makes no sense.
Science tells us
hitting his head
would only cure him
if hitting his head
was the original cause.
Told you
it was controversial.
Here at Greendale,
we accept all students,
whoever they may be
or have forgotten they were.
But assisting
in Kevin's recovery
has put a financial strain
on the school.
That's why
we are appealing
to the MacGuffin
Neurological Institute
for this $40,000 grant,
so we can continue
to fight
this terrible disease
and hopefully, one day,
pay for this documentary.
How was that, Abed?
That's too beggy?
ABED:
No, that was great.
But I could use
a new camera,
with a smoother zoom.
Oh, okay.
Well, just be sure
to get my good side, okay?
This documentary
needs to be convincing.
This needs to be
the  Hoop Dreams
of things people care about.
We rolling?
The dean
wants a propaganda film,
but I intend to explore
all sides
of this serious issue,
including those who don't
think it's a serious issue.
Hey, Jeff.
What are you doing?
Making a documentary
on Changnesia.
You gotta be
(BLEEP) kidding me.
ABED: Got it.
Beautiful.
All right,
let's get one more
for safety.
Jeff, back to one.
Jeff?
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
I'm telling you,
we should have sprung
for the name
Brand Glitter.
Look, cheap glitter,
expensive glitter.
Money talks, people.
Guys, did you hear?
The history
of ice cream class
had another heart attack.
Three more,
and we're all in.
Yes.
What's the
MacGuffin Institute?
PIERCE: Fine.
I'll tell him.
But one day,
you'll all be old and slow
and lose at things,
and when that day comes,
I won't remember
what I'm doing now.
Lord, the MacGuffin Institute
is coming to Greendale
on Friday
because they might
give the school money
to study Changnesia.
Changnesia isn't a disease.
It's a con.
You're seriously
helping this lunatic?
He kept the dean
in a dungeon.
He tried
to kill us.
He ate his twin
in utero.
That was Chang.
This is Kevin.
They're the same idiot.
How would you know?
Have you ever even
spent any time with him, Jeff?
I was reluctant
to accept Kevin
at first, too,
but he's just so sweet.
The world is
brand new to him.
He approaches everything
with the wonderment
of a small child
or a cartoon alien.
Whoa.
This makes
things smaller.
No, no...
Bigger.
Oh, bigger.
Well, enjoy
your collective delusion.
I'm going to go
get a sandwich,
which, unlike Changnesia,
is real.
Jeff, Jeff, Jeff, Jeff, Jeff,
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
We want to know
how you feel
about the
MacGuffin people visiting.
I need it on camera.
It's stupid.
What's stupid?
The whole thing.
Okay, put it together
for me.
"The whole thing is stupid."
All right, thanks, buddy.
I'll cut it together.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Shirley.
Hmm?
You don't seriously think
Chang is Kevin, do you?
No, I believe the good Lord
made Chang Chang.
Kevin is a choice.
Thank you.
I'm seriously worried
about the rest of the group.
Not only have they
drunk the Kevin kool-aid,
they're in
the study room
right now,
making banners,
debating glitter...
Well, I'd love
to keep talking about this,
but I gotta
get to work.
No, Shirley,
you've got to
help me stop this.
You're the only
sane person left.
Welcome
to Shirley's Sandwiches,
where the food
is Kevin-ly.
You hired Chang?
Hmm?
The customers
love Kevin.
I think it's because
he's a good listener.
Most words are new to him,
so it's all
still fascinating.
I'm Kevin.
And you are?
Not calling you Kevin.
Hi,
not calling you Kevin.
What are you having?
None of this.
Okay.
Uh, listen.
I don't care
what he calls himself,
he's a hard worker.
We're all broken people,
Jeffrey,
we all deserve
a second chance.
Like how I gave Andre
It doesn't mean I forgot.
I just forgave.
Chang didn't sleep
with a stripper.
He tried
to kill us.
Why does everyone
keep forgetting
about that?
But he didn't.
And you used
to be a sleazy lawyer.
What if Greendale never
gave you a second chance?
JEFF:  What Shirley said
really made me think.
I mean, all my friends
believe this guy.
What does it say about me
that I don't?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Hmm?
Yes?
Ugh, and cue
wet blanket Winger
to tell us
that we're all
wasting our time.
Actually, no.
I had a really good
conversation with Shirley,
and I realized
I've been acting like a jerk.
If it's not too late,
I'd love to help out
in any way I can.
Jeffrey,
that's amazing.
I knew
you'd come around.
All right, Abed,
get us in
panning singles.
And can you say "powwow"
Instead of "conversation"?
It just sounds more you.
All right, action.
Okay, you going
to make an entrance?
Great.
What does it say?
It says
I have gullible friends
who will believe anybody,
and I need
to make that anybody me.
By exposing Chang
in front of the whole school.
ABED: Wow.
Much like
the classic documentary
Capturing the Friedmans,
my story just took
a completely
unexpected turn.
Jeff, if you want
this done right,
I'm going to need
a steadicam for Garrett.
That's showbiz.
(SHOUTS)
(CRASHES)
ANNIE:  We were all
pretty happy
when Jeff came around.
He became really gung-ho
about Abed's documentary,
and had a lot
of great ideas
about how to impress
the MacGuffin people.
And that's why Pierce
should host the reception.
He speaks their language.
Finally, somebody's
making some sense.
I've got a blackface
Senor Wences bit
I've been workshopping.
Perfect.
Annie, we need
to find out
what happened to Kevin before
he showed up at Greendale.
What hellish experiences
did he overcome
during those missing months?
Do you think you can
use your forensic knowhow
to do some investigating?
Investigating?
Obvi.
Can I help?
If you're willing
to learn,
sure, partner.
"Partner."
I like that.
I'm going
to call you "Houlihan."
"Partner" and "Houlihan."
JEFF: Okay.
The postman
found Kevin here.
He said he was soaking wet
and smelled like fish.
I know it's not a lot
to go on...
Um, it's almost
too much to go on.
Look, Sullivan's trout farm
is just 1/4 mile away.
Who do you think
you're dealing with,
Winger?
I don't know, Houlihan.
Seems sort of thin.
In an investigation,
one dude always
has to go opposite
the other dude.
That's how they
get things done.
Well, you guys
can work it out.
Yeah, we will.
No, we won't.
Britta, Shirley...
SHIRLEY:
Oh, that's me.
I want you
to take this camera
and follow Chang around
for his day-to-day.
Really get into the life
of a functioning
Changnesiac.
I want you to go
inside his home, work, pod.
Just get everything.
Ooh, that's great advertising
for my growing business.
Okay, I'll do it.
And with
my photography skills...
Jeff, thank you.
When the dean told me
you were going to help me,
I couldn't believe it.
A cool, smart lawyer
like yourself
reaching out
to a little nobody like me?
I never told you
I was a lawyer.
No, you didn't.
Shirley said it,
remember?
You said,
"You hired Chang?"
And I said,
"I'm Kevin,
and you are?"
And you said,
"Not calling you Kevin,"
and I said,
"Hi, not calling you Kevin.
What are you having?"
And you said,
"None of this."
And then Shirley said,
"I don't care
what he calls himself.
"He's a hard worker.
"We're all broken people,
and we all
deserve a second chance.
"Like how I gave Andre
a second chance.
"Doesn't mean I forgot.
I just forgave."
And you said,
"Chang didn't sleep
with a stripper.
"He tried
to kill us.
"Why does everyone keep
forgetting all that?"
And then Shirley said,
"But he didn't.
"And you used
to be a sleazy lawyer."
Her words.
Wow.
That's quite a memory
you have.
Well, my short term memory
has actually improved.
My doctor
calls it a, um...
Side effect.
JEFF:  Oh.
Well played, Chang.
The chess match has begun.
What...
I'm Chinese?
Do you want
to get some footage
while we're waiting
for Kevin?
SHIRLEY: Maybe we could
take some shots
of my delicious
bread baking,
or the affordable prices
on our new
Shirley's Sandwiches
super saver menu.
Or we could
get to know
the Shirley
behind the sandwiches.
Here,
give me that camera.
Oh. Okay.
Be careful, now.
It's Abed's camera.
All right.
Watch it.
BRITTA: Oh, where is
the stop button on this?
Oh, here it is.
Okay.
You want
to hear my pitch?
Mmm-hmm.
A strong,
independent woman,
starting her own business.
An "entrepreneu-her,"
If you will.
Or maybe
a businesswoman?
Okay, fine.
Think inside the box.
All right.
Are you ready?
Mmm-hmm.
Action.
(WHIMPERING)
Cut. Oh! Beautiful.
You don't think
the song was too much?
Are you kidding me?
It made the scene.
You know what?
I want to get
some better lighting
up in this noise.
Let's go
hit up Abed.
I never told anybody
that story, Britta.
Oh, it was beautiful.
SHIRLEY: I was dead
for three minutes.
BRITTA: Three minutes?
SHIRLEY: Three whole minutes.
They thought I was gone.
Pierce.
How's your act coming?
Blackface  Senor Wences?
Mmm-hmm.
How do you
think it's coming?
(LAUGHING)
In the unlikely event
I fail to expose Chang,
I'm pretty confident
Pierce will make sure
we don't get a grant.
What you talkin'
about, honkey?
Wow, that bit could not
get any more perfect.
Wait a minute.
I haven't introduced you
to my Asian wife yet.
(HIGH-PITCHED)
Uh-oh...
I was wrong.
(HUMMING)
This is the place.
No, it's not.
(SIGHS)
(DOG BARKING)
Garrett,
here he comes.
Get up.
I can't.
It's too heavy!
Garrett, now.
Now.
(GARRETT BREATHING HEAVILY)
Excuse me,
Mr. Sullivan.
This is Houlihan.
I'm her partner, Partner.
Wait, I'm Partner.
No, you're not.
We'd like to ask you
a couple of questions.
What are you,
the Trout Police?
Because if you are,
you're legally bound
to tell me,
or else it's entrapment.
We're not
the Trout Police.
Have you seen
this man?
One morning, I see something
coming out of the trout tank,
and at first,
I was scared,
because, uh,
I'm the last face
that a lot of trout
ever see.
I'm not saying that
the trout
are a vengeful breed,
but if they were, I...
I'd probably be
public enemy number one.
(CHUCKLES)
So the figure that emerged,
it was that man?
Yeah,
and I was pretty relieved
when I found out
it was a naked Asian guy,
and not an angry trout.
And when was this?
Oh, it must have been
around June.
I remember because
my milkweed allergies
were acting up
something fierce.
I gave him some clothes,
and sent him on his way
the next morning.
I don't know
what happened to him
after that.
Mr. Sullivan,
how many employees
do you have here?
Employees?
What do I look like,
Trout World?
(LAUGHS)
No employees.
Heh, just me.
(DOG BARKING)
And my dog.
ANNIE:  I knew he was
hiding something.
A spike in production
in June,
at the peak
of milkweed allergy season?
Something on this trout farm
was starting to smell...
Wrong.
The problem was,
I didn't have any way
to make him talk.
Or did I?
Well, looks like
everything checks out here.
Right, Troy?
No, Houlihan,
I don't think
anything checks out here.
No, don't fly
off the handle, Partner.
Oh, I will fly
off the handle, Houlihan.
What the hell
are you talking about?
I'm sorry,
Mr. Sullivan.
Clearly, you have
nothing to hide.
What are you hiding?
Fine!
(DOG BARKING)
You got me.
I've been using
that Asian guy as unpaid,
manual labor
for three months
before I drove him
into town.
But he wanted me to!
We were friends,
and I treated him
with respect and dignity.
Partner and Houlihan.
(DOG BARKING)
Shut up, Kevin!
BOTH: (WHISPERING)
Partner and Houlihan.
JEFF: I don't understand.
Why would he work
for no money?
Because he doesn't know
about money.
Kevin doesn't know
about labor laws,
or 40-hour work weeks,
or that that dude named him
after a dog.
Growing up,
I had a cat named Troy,
a bird named Troy,
and a hamster named Troy.
They were all
older than me.
Oh, my God.
I think Kevin's struggle
just got a lot sexier,
grant-wise.
This is horrible.
JEFF:  It was horrible.
They were supposed to
come back with a smoking gun,
and all they found
was a little
human rights abuse.
Which, normally,
is terrible.
ABED: So do you
believe Kevin now?
No.
I want all your footage.
I know
Chang slipped up.
He's not smart enough
to play dumb all the time.
What about
Shirley and Britta's footage?
It's unusable crap.
I don't care.
I want it all.
Do you want it bad enough
to rent me a crane?
And maybe license
an expensive song?
Yeah, whatever.
♪ The itsy-bitsy spider
♪ Went up the water spout ♪
Unusable crap
is generous.
It goes on like this
for another 12 hours.
I couldn't even
get through it all,
and I sat through
The Tree of Life.
Wait, right there.
What's that?
Oh, come on,
you slippery snake, slip up.
Doubtful.
When he's alone,
he mostly just practices
smiling and frowning.
We've all done it.
(PHONE DIALING)
ABED: Who's he calling?
JEFF: Good question.
We figure that out,
we've got
our smoking gun.
And all thanks
to Britta.
Don't ruin this.
ABED:  The stage was set
for a climatic
final set piece.
The MacGuffin people
were on campus,
and Jeff had prepared
quite the presentation.
(HIGH-PITCHED GIBBERISH)
You shut up.
(HIGH-PITCHED)
But I love you.
You get yourself
in the kitchen,
and make me a burrito.
Oh, okay, yay!
Oh, thank you.
Okay, thank you,
Pierce Hawthorne
for your special blend
of playful racial humor.
PELTON: And genuine thoughts
on Geraldine Ferraro.
(CHUCKLES)
He's an old teddy bear.
And now, I believe
Jeff Winger
has a presentation.
Yay.
Ugh.
Thank you.
I must confess,
I was just
a short while ago
quite skeptical
about Changnesia.
But, with the help
of my friends,
we have uncovered a lot
about this terrible,
newly-discovered,
completely real disease.
I think you'll find it
as eye-opening as I did.
Wait till you see
what we found.
Kevin was a victim
of human trafficking.
Our purpose here tonight
is to help cure Kevin
of his Changnesia.
Who better
to jog his memory
than someone special
from his allegedly
erased past.
So please welcome
to the stage
the former Mrs. Ben Chang,
Alessandra.
Alessandra,
come on up.
Thank you.
Ben...
Do you remember me?
I'm sorry.
I don't.
Admit it, Kevin.
You remember her.
This is the woman
you never stopped loving.
Hit the lights!
(PHONE DIALING ON SCREEN)
(ALL GASP)
Oh...
You love her so much,
you called her
over and over
and over again,
even though you don't
know her
or how to use a phone
or what a number is.
(ALL GASP)
ALESSANDRA:
What's going on here?
You told me
I was here to help him.
Oh, we are here
to help him, all right.
We are here
to help him admit
that he has been faking
this whole time.
Where'd you get
the number, Chang?
I found it in the vents!
It's 555-0190.
And it was the most
beautiful thing
I'd ever seen.
But I always hung up,
because...
I didn't know
if the person
on the other end
would ever want
to talk to Kevin...
After knowing Chang.
You seem so nice.
If we were
really married,
I wish I could remember
for even one moment
how lucky I was.
Oh...
Aw...
Oh, Ben.
(GIGGLING)
Uh!
(THUDS)
(ALL GASP)
Jeffrey,
what are you doing?
Look, if he doesn't
remember her,
then this wouldn't
bother him.
My logic is flawless!
(ALL SHRIEK,
SHOCKED CHATTER)
Doesn't that bother you?
That bothers you!
ABED:  Things got so ugly,
I hesitate to even
show you this footage.
But I will let you see
me reacting to it.
That'll probably be
more than you can handle.
(SHOCKED CHATTER)
Mmm...
Actually,
it's not that bad,
but this keeps
the story moving.
Hey, Alessandra,
his last girlfriend
was a charred mannequin leg!
Jeffrey!
Have you lost your mind?
You never
believed Kevin?
You were just lying
to manipulate us
into helping you hurt him?
Jeffrey, I trusted you
and believed in you
and fantasized about
celebrating over mimosas
with you!
Dean, if this is the sort
of uphill battle
you're facing in the fight
against Changnesia,
well, then,
you're gonna need
all the help you can get.
On behalf of the MacGuffin
Neurological Institute,
grant granted.
(ALL EXCLAIM)
(EXCITED CHATTER)
JEFF:  So...
I guess I did help.
Just not in the way
I wanted to.
But, on the bright side,
this is the most
well-documented failure
of my life.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Thank you.
JEFF:  By trying to make
Kevin a pariah,
I accidentally
became more Chang
than Chang
at his Changiest.
(LAUGHS)
That's funny.
Well, I didn't try
to kill anyone.
Which no one
seems to care about.
But you know
what I'm saying.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Can I sit here?
You sure you want
to be seen with me?
You have a brand-new
reputation to uphold.
(CHUCKLES)
I like you.
Really?
Even after
everything I did to...
Whoever you are?
(CHUCKLES)
Okay, I get it.
Changnesia's hard
to understand.
At least, that's what
people tell me.
Now, I don't know
a thing about it,
which apparently
is one of the symptoms,
and it's so frustrating.
Look, I know Chang
was a bad guy.
So he probably deserved
everything you did to him.
But you're not a bad guy.
You just made a mistake.
And I'm willing
to start over fresh
if you are.
Hi.
My name's Kevin.
JEFF:  I'm not saying
I believe him.
But I have got an idea
of what it feels like
to be Chang.
Wanting to leave
that name behind
is the sanest decision
anyone can make.
(NEW RADICALS'
YOU GET WHAT YOU GIVE)
♪ 1, 2
Hi.
♪ 1, 2, 3
I'm Jeff.
♪ But when
the night is falling
♪ You cannot find the light ♪
ALL: Aw.
Thanks.
A lot of filmmakers
use crane shots
to elicit emotion.
What the heck, Abed?
You knew what Jeffrey
was planning to do
the whole time?
Why can't you ever
make a documentary
about the thing you plan
to make a documentary about?
Don't censor him!
Censorship.
(GASPS)
This is the documentary.
Ugh.
Abed, you gotta teach me
how to use that camera.
(IMITATES GUNSHOT)
Guys... I'm sorry.
I really screwed up.
I hope you can
forgive me.
Already forgotten.
(LAUGHTER)
Oh...
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
SHIRLEY: Kevin...
What are we
laughing about?
JEFF: Oh, Kevin.
ALL: Kevin...
(LAUGHTER)
Adorable.
Good job.
I don't get it.
(CHUCKLES)
(HAUNTING MUSIC)
(DIALING PHONE)
Hi, it's me.
They all finally bought it.
Hook, line, and Winger.
I patiently await
your further instructions.
Chang out.
(CHUCKLING)
(CACKLING MANIACALLY)
Why did I do that?
Man...
(CACKLING MANIACALLY)