His name
is Archie Decoste.
Age, 22,
total years spent
in high school, seven.
SAT score zero.
And he was
recently arrested
for selling marijuana
to a police officer
at a police station.
So, you want us
to help you
recruit this idiot
instead of an honors student
or a science genius?
Do we go
to the same Greendale?
Ah, but let me reveal
the fortune inside
this cookie.
Family net worth,
$8 million.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is what we
in the community college
recruiting game
call a "whale."
The perfect mix
of low intellect,
high lack of ambition,
and limitless
parental support.
So, a rich dumb-dumb
who will never graduate
and keep dropping money
into the school indefinitely.
Got it.
Is there really
that much money
in this, Dean,
or is it like
that endorsement deal
you made
with Let's potato chips?
If you don't like
the crispy-licious taste
of Let's,
feel free to eat
that other greasy brand.
Splingles?
Not this guy.
Thank you, Troy,
and, I will explain
the value
of this whale
by describing one
who's been swimming
right under your nose.
Pierce Hawthorne
has taken 80%
of Greendale's classes
more than twice.
He is the only
Greendale student
who has ever paid
for a premium locker
or the extended
pencil warranty.
Pierce cannot know
about this.
He's a big baby
who throws tantrums
when anyone else
gets attention.
Remember when Kerri Strug
visited our campus?
That was horrible.
That was awful.
I have scheduled
Archie's visit for tomorrow
when Pierce
has no classes.
Guys, I'm asking,
as treasurer
of the Forensics Club.
The dean said we could use
some of the whale money
for a new body farm.
Mmm.
Who wants to help?
I'm in.
Sounds like a romper.
We do need money.
The biology department's
been dissecting
the same dead pig
for 10 years.
If we land this kid,
we can buy
100 dead pigs
and make everybody happy.
I'll help where I can,
but I started
a new PE class.
I've been avoiding it
for three years,
but you can't run
from running forever.
I'm in PE too.
I made room
in my trophy case.
Then, I remembered
classes don't
give out trophies,
so I put a fishbowl
there instead.
It's been quite
the week.
So, the rest of us
will have to pick up
the slack,
and, yes, Jeffrey,
I assume you're out,
because of
your track record
of literally being
too cool for school.
Actually, you can
count me in on this one.
What?
(ALL REACT)
You had me at
"no Pierce."
He's been all over me
lately to hang out.
It's weird.
You just want to be
a part of something.
Admit it,
Thanksgiving softened
that Winger underbelly.
Ugh, Britta.
Now, let's set sail
and hunt that whale!
Yeah.
Hey, let's do that.
Oh!
You know
what the commercial says.
"Keep your damn hands
off my Let's."
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
Hey, Jeff,
there you are.
I was thinking
we could swing by
this great barbershop I know.
You're looking
a little stubbly,
and nobody handles a razor
like an Italian.
They develop nimble fingers
from pleasing
their mistresses.
Thank you for
opening my eyes
to two new stereotypes.
Now, how can
I put this?
No.
I don't want to go.
Not now, not ever.
No.
No prob.
We'll work
around your skedge.
Ah.
It's okay.
Pierce is gone.
ALL: Yes.
Walking dead
has left the building.
Resume operation,
deadliest catch.
Archie is gonna love
this banner.
The name,
brand glitter
really shows.
Yo, yo, yo.
School board guys
in the hizzie!
Richie, Richie,
pace yourself.
Hey, there, Dean.
Just thought
we'd pop in
and check
on the big whale hunt.
Ah, what a day we have
planned for young Archie.
Library tour,
calculator
lab demonstration...
And,
it all culminates
in the
"spirit of Greendale"
reception.
Magnitude
is a soft yes.
Oh, wow,
that's a get.
As much as we love
that Magnitude,
your tour may be
lacking a little...
Tour sucks, bro.
What?
You gotta think big.
Hookers, blow,
hookers.
He's been mixing,
but there is
some wisdom there.
We need
this whale money.
The kid
likes snowboarding.
Maybe Shaun White
finds his way
on the faculty roster.
He likes to party.
Maybe Greendale
suddenly has a frat.
The Delta Cubes,
or whatever.
Dean, you're not
considering this, are you?
No, no.
Greendale stands
on its own.
No hookers,
no blow,
no Shaun White frat.
College dean
threatening a fraternity.
You'll never shut down
the Delta Cubes.
What?
Delta Cubes,
Delta Cubes, Delta Cubes...
Look,
it's your call, Craig.
Don't let this whale
swim away.
Cruise by
Skeeper's Express
for a refill?
I'll second that motion.
(SIGHS)
I've been working
on my victory dances.
Basketball,
football,
and crab soccer.
That one's the hard one.
Well, that's nice.
Hey, when I was
in grade school,
PE was about
being picked on
and picked last,
but, you'll put me
on your team, right?
Right, but also, wrong.
Ah.
PE's about
survival of the fittest.
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Line up, class.
Welcome to PEE
I'm Coach Jason Chapman.
Physical education
education?
I thought that was a typo
in the course cartalogue.
It started as a typo,
but it's grown
into one of Greendale's
most successful programs.
Anyone can take PE.
I teach my student coaches
to teach PE.
(SCOFFS)
Something funny,
Coach Barnes?
No, it's just...
You're teaching us
how to be gym teachers.
Gym teachers?
A gym
is a building,
a man-made structure
inside which
Physical Education
teachers
teach Physical Education
to Physical
Education students.
Pop quiz,
Coach Barnes,
a student is choking
on a plastic golf ball.
What do you do?
I...
How many
orange cones
does it take
to line
a regulation soccer field?
What if students
are talking
during stretches?
When my kids
talk past bedtime,
I use my angry voice,
and I say,
"The next peep I hear
will be the last."
And I give 'em
one of these.
Not bad,
Coach Bennett.
(CHUCKLES)
Look at me!
I see you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Two hours late?
This is exactly the lack
of follow-through
that makes Archie
so appealing,
but still,
send a text, right?
Okay, Abed,
I told you
we're not doing
the fraternity idea.
The Delta Cubes
will never die.
We've only just
begun to fight.
You only
began yesterday.
Whale, ho!
Look alive, everyone.
Hey, what are you guys
all doing out here?
Oh, no!
Pierce will ruin
everything!
What's an Archie?
Why does he get a banner?
Jeff!
Do something.
Oh!
(WHIMPERS)
Ugh.
There you are, Pierce.
Thought you were
gonna cancel our plans.
Plans?
To spend the entire day
together away
from everyone else.
Oh, yeah!
Those plans.
(CHUCKLES)
Suck it, bozos.
You're getting ditched
by the cool kids.
Oh, what a day
we're gonna have.
Text me the instant
I can ditch him.
Oh!
Hey, guys.
Sweet campus.
Welcome to Greendale.
I'm Bean Pelton.
"Bean Pelton?"
Dean Pelton.
(CHUCKLES)
Gosh, I'm nervous.
Please enroll
in our school.
Please, please.
Nice scooter, Archie.
Yeah, City College
gave it to me
as a present.
City College?
Mmm-hmm.
City College
bought you a vespa?
Brand-new.
(LAUGHS)
So, Archie,
have you heard about
our half-pipes
and hash pipes class,
taught by professor
Shaun White?
What?
Yeah, let me tell you
about it
in our Mountain Dew
cool zone tent.
Put up a tent,
write "Mountain Dew" on it,
make it cool.
Ah, here we go.
Let's keep going.
This is our library.
Okay.
Archie, why don't you
"hang ten" on the web
while I talk business,
and you know what?
You can take
that computer.
ARCHIE: Wah!
Sweet!
My friends and I
can drop it off
an overpass.
Ah, I shouldn't
have heard that.
Dean, you're giving him
our computers?
He is
a 22-year-old
stoner-head
whose parents
bought him a GED.
Which college is he
going to choose?
Vespa state, or
"ooh, look at our library"
university?
Those school board guys
were right.
Britta,
where do we get drugs?
Really?
Look who stumbled
onto the high road.
This is
a slippery slope.
Well, City College
slipped that slope
when they slipped him
that scooter,
but they sure slipped up
when they let him
set foot on our soil.
CHAPMAN:
Three, two, one!
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Time!
Coach Barnes,
it seems
dodge ball storage
isn't quite
in your skill set,
much like
table tennis prep.
(LAUGHTER)
Excellent job,
Coach Bennett.
(SIGHS)
You have
the spatial reasoning skills
of a young Kevin Miller,
a really good PE teacher
I know.
The skill of
ranking others in order
of ability is crucial.
In this next drill,
our two best
student coaches
will split the rest
of the class,
Coach Bennett,
Coach Neil.
Yeah!
Pick your teams.
Coach Donovan.
Coach Goldman.
Coach Mckenna.
Coach Cutler.
Coach Winston.
Ooh, Coach Dornetto.
Coach Guest.
Coach Panos!
Oh.
CHAPMAN:
Choose wisely.
You're one decision away
from victory or defeat.
(SIGHS)
Coach... Marzec.
Oh, yay!
(CHAPMAN GROANS)
CHAPMAN: Well picked,
Coach Bennett.
Your team wins!
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
SHIRLEY: Oh, we won!
Nice!
PIERCE: Ah,
the barbershop.
A reminder of a bygone era
when men were men,
and women were
sex cooks
who did laundry.
I've been getting
a daily shave here
for decades.
And apparently,
reading the same
eight magazines
the entire time.
Yeah,  National Geographic's
got some
tribal boob shots
that are exquisite.
There's something
about a breast
that's never been touched
by white hands.
You are
a complicated man.
PIERCE: Silvio, spin up
lucky number seven.
('50S CROONER MUSIC PLAYING)
You know what?
That feels good,
I'll give you that.
Now, that soda goblet
gets you free refills
in the cafeteria,
and it was painted
by our professor Ed Hardy...
Whoa!
PELTON: Who teaches
Bikini class.
Oh, yeah!
(LAUGHTER)
Whoa, check out
that bling!
(SNAPS)
I want that.
You heard him, Annie!
Bling the king!
Yeah, just take it
off of him.
There you go.
Thank you.
Delta Cubes!
Prepare to bond
through embarrassment.
Pacifiers in!
Commence...
Code Dean!
Gosh Dean it, Abed!
I told you, no fraternities!
(CRIES)
There's soda
all over my kicks!
Britta, give Archie
your scarf so he can
dry his kicks.
Dry his kicks, Britta.
Put your back into it!
No!
Line drawn!
If I wanted to wait
on a rich man hand and foot,
I would've gone to Dubai
what that sheik
I met at Trader Joe's.
(SCREAMS)
Don't worry
about her, Archie.
(CHUCKLES)
Onward to
the microbrew pizzatorium!
I think all a man
needs in life
is a close shave,
a cold beer,
and you know,
maybe a faithful dog.
Hmm, I had a chocolate lab
growing up, Rosie.
Oh.
She used to
wake me up every morning
by licking my feet.
Mine was Walter,
a German shepherd.
Followed me to school
every day.
I'd look out the window,
and there he was,
dropping
a steaming fat one
on the lawn.
Would someone
please tell me
why I've been shaving
my own face
all these years
like a sucker?
(CHUCKLES)
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
This state-of-the-art
mock locker room,
or "mocker room,"
simulates the conditions
of an actual locker room.
Don't we have
an actual locker room?
You think you're ready
for that, Coach Barnes?
(LAUGHTER)
For our next drill,
drama students
will play the role
of PE students,
and each of you
will oversee them
in a "mocker room"
setting.
My character
just had
her first period.
Mine has eczema!
Coach Bennett,
care to go first?
Yes!
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Keep yo hands
to yourself!
Running will get you
five laps, Mister!
Ow!
Joey!
I will come in
that shower
and kick yo bare ass!
JOEY: Sorry,
Coach Bennett.
I have never seen such
natural disciplinary skills.
You're up next,
Coach Barnes.
Entertain us
with your ineptitude.
(LAUGHTER)
How's the foam machine
coming, Leonard?
Memories
will be made tonight.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
PELTON: Destiny!
Oh, thank you for coming
on such short notice.
Well, I did get
your Christmas card.
Look... No, so...
No, no,
no time to pre-party.
You and the girls
get in position
and wait for my signal.
Strippers?
(GASPS)
Oh, tons.
(CHUCKLES)
It's good for the school.
Mmm-hmm.
The whale is here.
Balloon drop, go!
(THUMPING TECHNO MUSIC)
There you go.
Release the whores.
PELTON: Oh, yeah.
ARCHIE: No way!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Pierce.
I was wrong
about this shop.
It really is special.
Well, if you
like the place so much,
why don't you gay marry it?
(LAUGHTER)
(SIGHS)
You probably
didn't notice it, Jeff,
but I've been subtly
trying to get us
some alone time.
I might've picked up
on that.
I'm no stranger
to father issues,
so I know confronting
your dad couldn't have
been easy,
and I just want to say
I'm proud of you.
Well...
If you're so proud...
Why don't you
gay marry me?
(LAUGHTER)
You guys, behave!
Hit the showers!
Everybody in the showers!
Please stop hitting
each other!
Hit the showers!
Cut! Scene!
Shirley, help.
I can't control
these drama students
or their characters.
No! No!
PE is survival
of the fittest, Troy.
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHTER)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hey,
your phone's buzzing.
Ooh, it's from Annie.
You sly dog.
"Need more time.
Keep Pierce busy."
Keep me busy?
Look, the group is giving
some big shot a tour,
so it's my job
to keep you busy.
You know
how you get jealous.
So, that's why
you spent the day
with me?
You drew
the short straw.
Well,
that's how it started,
but I really did end up
having a good time.
Yeah, I used to
regret not having
a son to bring here.
I'm glad
I didn't have kids.
They just end up
disappointing you.
(SIGHS)
(BELL ON DOOR CHIMES)
(THUMPING TECHNO MUSIC)
So Archie,
having a good time?
Gettin' crazy
up in this club?
Sicker than ever, bro!
I've made
my decision, Dean.
I'm about to get all up
in this Greendale.
(LAUGHS)
Whoo!
Human beings,
it's official!
Say hello
to our newest Greendalian,
Archie Decoste!
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Pop pop!
ALL: Pop pop!
I want that
to be my thing now.
I don't think
you can do that.
Magnitude, you're not
to say "pop pop"
ever again.
Not pop?
That's right.
Find a new thing.
Get him out of here.
Ah! Here we go!
We're back!
(LAUGHS)
♪ Get dirty
(IN SLOW MOTION)
Pop pop!
♪ She's a dirty girl ♪
Well, we did it.
We did what we had to do,
and I feel great
about it.
It's all for Greendale.
All for Greendale.
Oh, you look
pretty sad for someone
whose Forensics Club
can now afford
that state-of-the-art
body farm.
Mmm!
I can smell
the corpses now.
None of this
is weighing on you?
(CHUCKLES)
Sha!
The only thing
weighing on me is tons
and tons of whale money.
Ah, Jeffrey.
Hey.
Landed a whale, huh?
Yeah, but I'm starting
to feel like
maybe we...
Okay, Archie
goes to Greendale now.
We're moving forward,
Annie!
Okay, we all
paid a price.
You don't hear
Jeffrey grumbling,
and, he had to spend
a whole day
with walking dead.
Well, that's true.
You know what?
I can't believe
I'm gonna say this.
Don't talk about Pierce
like that.
Look, maybe
the only reason
he can be
so unpleasant
is because
we expect him to be.
If we don't treat him
like such a dick...
Well, he'll probably
still be one
98% of the time,
but the 2%
he's tolerable,
it might be worth it.
(SCOFFS)
Well, who put the salt
in his cereal, huh?
Look, I, for one,
am still proud of what
we did for Greendale.
(OMINOUS SCRAPING)
(GASPS)
I've been up
all night trying out
new catchphrases.
Diggity doo?
My God,
what have we done?
I thought
you dropped PEE.
I did,
but I lost my keys
in the mocker.
I had to hitchhike home
last night
in a burrito truck.
It's not as fun
as it sounds.
I'm sorry
for how I acted
in class.
Don't apologize.
You were the fittest,
and you survived.
Still, no one deserves
to be mocked
for being mock-locked
in a mock locker.
Friends should help
friends survive.
Ah! Oh, geez!
Hi.
Ah, ah, ah!
So, I'm going
to help you learn
to teach the most
unteachable student
there is.
(SLURPS)
♪ Teachers teaching
to teach
♪ Coaches coaching
to coach
♪ You've gotta
dig down deep
♪ To prove you want it
the most
♪ Get your
Physical Education
♪ Education
♪ There's no room
in the gym
for hesitation
♪ PEE is not PE
♪ It's a totally
different philosophy
♪ It's Physical Education
♪ Education ♪
Well done,
Coach Barnes.
I can't breathe.
You as well,
Coach Bennett.
You know,
I was supposed to
teach you two
to teach other people,
but instead,
you ended up
teaching me.
Oh.
(PANTS)
I did it!
I used
the water fountain.
Archie, wake up!
Chillax, bro.
It's not even noon.
I will neither chill
nor relax.
All this hoopla
is not what
Greendale really is.
Greendale is
a nice welcome banner.
a foamless cafeteria.
And Greendale is
Magnitude saying
"Pop pop."
Now, I am a man
of very little integrity,
and I let students get away
with practically anything
on this campus,
but I will not
allow Greendale
to lose the things
that make it Greendale.
Now, Archie,
I would love for you
to enroll in my school,
but I will not
change it for you.
Greendale
will stay Greendale,
no matter what.
You know what?
Everybody kisses my ass
because my dad is loaded,
and they always give me
free stuff,
like that jet ski
I sunk,
but it would be
pretty sweet
to be treated
like a normal dude...
(LAUGHS)
So I'm in.
(SIGHS)
Magnitude.
You usually
have the perfect blend
of brevity and wit
that sums up
situations like this.
Pop pop!
Yay!
Oh, that's so good!
So good!
I think
we all learned today
that all human beings
deserve dignity.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
ALL: Delta Cubes!
Delta Cubes!
Delta Cubes! Delta Cubes!
Delta Cubes,
operation, slack attack!
Slack attack?
Ah!
ALL: Delta Cubes!
Delta Cubes!
Mark my words,
Delta Cubes,
you'll pay for this!
(EXHALES)
♪ I've even been
to paradise
Is this seat taken?
Free country.
♪ Christopher Columbus
may have reached... ♪
You know,
I was thinking
I might start coming here
more often.
I like the vibe.
You know what sport
I never got?
Golf.
No argument here.
They lost me immediately
with the clown clothes.
You know,
I belong to a dozen
country clubs.
Never played.
I just spend my time
hitting on the waitresses.
There's something
about a country club
waitress
that just makes you wanna
pay your dues every year.
♪ Let's snack it up
♪ Let's do it right
♪ Let's taste the crisp
with the flavor and crunch
♪ With all our might
♪ Let's grab a bag
♪ Let's take a bite
♪ Let's grab potato chips,
let's do it right... ♪
Get your damn hand
off of my Let's!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Honestly, after all that,
you still eat Splingles?
Uh, yeah, Troy.
Splingles
have 30% less fat.
They're the fit chip.
You know,
I kinda have a headache.
Maybe you should
go home.