And then
in the season finale,
they reveal the whole thing
was a dream,
when the inspector
wakes up
next to a very young
and very topless Cheryl Tiegs.
(GROANING)
Even Pierce loves
this show now?
It's not
Inspector Spacetime.
It's the American version,
and it's a travesty.
It's broad, obvious, sexist,
and the timing is...
Honey, I'm Dean!
What the hell
is wrong with you?
Oh, Jeffrey,
you are too much.
(LAUGHS)
Why, I was doing
some house cleaning
the other day...
"Deana Reed" style...
When I realized,
"Gosh, golly,
"it's been ages
since we had a dance."
So, this Friday
we are going back to
Greendale's golden age
with an old-fashioned
sock hop!
(BOTH GIGGLING)
The health department
requires you wear shoes.
What a "coincidean."
You're throwing a dance
the same day
the CDC is confiscating
our drinking fountains.
Well...
Placating students
with a fun event.
Classic bread and circuses.
In ancient Rome,
the emperor would
distract the populace
from their problems
by allocating money
for free bread and circuses.
I've been making
a conscious effort
to get away
from filtering everything
through TV.
I figured it's time
I showed some growth.
It's been three
and a half seasons...
Is what the old me
would have said.
Oh.
Aw.
Anyhoo, it is
a Sadie Hawkins dance,
which means
girls ask the boys.
Oh, I love those!
So, ladies, get out there
and make yourselves useful.
(SNORTS) So you're saying
There's one day a year
when women are free
to choose their own mates.
What is this,
cave-person times?
Well I have already started
on a Sadie Hawkins banner,
so this thing
is pretty much
set in stone.
Well then maybe I'll throw
my own dance,
one that doesn't
conform to your
oppressive gender norms.
Give me a break.
You think a dance
can just be thrown
together willy-nilly?
You think
I decide to just do
a rain forest theme
and buy palm fronds
and rig the
sprinkler system to...
Hold on,
I gotta write this down.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
So, Britta, you're gonna
throw a protest dance?
Is that a thing?
It is now.
And instead of
Sadie Hawkins,
my dance will honor
a real feminist icon,
someone who worked
for women's rights
every day of the year...
Sophie B. Hawkins.
Oh...
It wasn't really...
You know what, Britta,
you're right.
A Sophie B. Hawkins dance
is just what
this school needs...
Thanks, Jeff.
To celebrate Sophie B. Hawkins
and all her accomplishments.
Jeez, Winger, who's throwing
this dance, me or you?
Um, Britta, I think
you meant to say
Susan B. Anthony,
not Sophie B. Hawkins.
Britta for the whoops!
Didn't you have a cat named
Susan B. Anthony?
How did you manage
to "Britta" that?
I didn't "Britta" anything.
I meant Sophie B. Hawkins.
Really?
Your plan was to
throw a dance
honoring the singer of
Damn I Wish I Was Your Lover?
And  As I Lay Me Down
which in my opinion
is the far superior song.
Ooh, that is a good song.
Yeah.
Yes.
I am throwing
a Sophie B. Hawkins dance.
(GASPS)
And it is gonna
be amazing,
and when people come
they're gonna be like,
"Damn! She straight
Britta'd' this!"
Because, that's right,
I'm taking it back!
You're really doing this?
Look, as someone who
faked being a lawyer
for seven years
I appreciate your
commitment to the bit,
but just admit
you were wrong.
So you can say
I "Britta'd" it?
Yes, of course.
That goes without saying.
But come on,
it was a small mistake.
Call this off before
it becomes a full-scale
"Brit-astrophe."
I coined that.
Jeff,
if you don't want
to come to my dance
you are free to go
to the Sadie Hawkins dance,
which will be happening
at the same time
across the cafeteria.
Our school has limited
venue options.
Oh, I wouldn't miss it.
Oh, and one last thing...
You do realize
that if you call it
a Sophie B. Hawkins dance
people will expect
Sophie B. Hawkins
to actually be there, right?
(LAUGHS) Yes.
And when she comes
I'm gonna be like,
"I Will Remember You
doubting me."
That's a Sarah Mclachlan song.
So, Abed, I was thinking
about what you said,
about showing growth,
and I was thinking
maybe one way
to do that is
to meet new people and...
Where's this going?
Can I set you up
with a date
for the Sadie Hawkins
day dance?
A blind date.
I've always thought
of myself as more of
an acquired taste...
Mmm.
But...okay.
Ooh, if you're open
to meeting someone,
there's a number
of eligible young ladies
in my church.
Shirley!
I'm already finding
a date for Abed.
I asked first.
There's no reason
we can't both help
Abed find someone.
Why don't we each
pick a girl
and then let Abed decide,
instead of making it
a competition.
That's exactly
So it is.
Only for the loser.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
I need the computer.
Pierce, there are, like,
dozens of computers.
Yeah, but my email is
on this one.
Pierce!
Jeez, what's up your butt?
I may have lied
this morning
about meeting
Sophie B. Hawkins
because I didn't want Jeff
to make fun of me,
and then I may have lied
to cover that lie,
and now I'm in deep...lies.
So what?
So you told a lie, big deal.
The important thing
is never to admit it.
Actually, I was thinking
about coming clean.
And give Winger
the satisfaction?
Hell, no.
Besides, anything could happen
between now and that dance.
An asteroid could hit.
Do you want to be
the schmuck who apologizes
just before the world ends?
That kind of makes sense.
Thank you.
Damn right
it makes sense.
You're talking
to the wisest man on campus.
Now seriously,
I need to get to my email.
The post office
is about to close.
Pierce!
Guys, check out
my friend Britta's
Sophie B. Hawkins dance.
I'll be spinning the hits
from yesterday and today,
which are basically
the same to me
since I have Changnesia.
That guy's like Teflon.
No matter how much
awful stuff he does,
he keep getting
another chance.
Yeah, he's like
the Colin Farrell of people.
You want to help me
with Britta's dance?
Could be a chance
for classic Troy
and Abed hijinks.
In the interest of growth
I'm trying to avoid hijinks,
as well as capers,
romps, and exploits.
Escapades are a gray area.
(CLEARS THROAT) Abed.
This is Kat.
Hi, Kat.
Nice to meet you.
She wants
to ask you something.
Isn't she
perfect for Abed?
She's like one of
those quirky girls
from the movies.
I saw her in the cafeteria
trying to pay for lunch
with a song.
(BALLOON SQUEAKS)
I asked if you'd go
to the Sadie Hawkins dance
with me into the balloon.
Could you hear it?
Sure, I'd be happy
to go with you.
Super duper Mister Cooper!
(CLICKS MOUTH)
Nice.
So, you chose the girl
I picked. (CHUCKLES)
It's cool. Not like
it was a competition
or anything.
Just be gentle
when you tell Shirley
that she was the loser.
Or do you
want me to tell her?
It's cool.
I'll handle it.
So, was that girl
an alien or a toddler
with a growing disease?
Hello, Abed.
I talked to a lovely girl
at my church
and she'd be happy to go
to the dance with you.
I appreciate it, Shirley,
but I...
I hope you will
at least consider it,
and not just because
saying "no" would
crush this poor girl,
but because
I don't want you
to miss out on the
opportunity of a lifetime.
You're right.
I'd love to go to
Britta's dance with her.
Oh, goody!
I'll set it up.
Oh, I hope
this doesn't hurt
Annie's feelings.
Maybe I should
go tell her.
No need.
I'll handle it.
Oh, okay.
Bye-bye. (GIGGLES)
At the risk of discovering
I'm living two parallel lives
like that guy in  Awake,
don't you already have
a date to the dance?
Yep.
Now I have two,
which means
I can do the classic
two dates in one night
sitcom trope.
I'll get to wear
two outfits.
Mix up their names.
Maybe hide under a table.
What about growth?
I tried to go in a more
grounded direction,
but I still ended up
in a comically
implausible situation.
It's like Shirley said,
it's a once in a lifetime
opportunity for hijinks.
I can't pass it up.
It seems like
you already passed up
a great opportunity
for hijinks.
I did?
Uh, duh doy!
Britta's dance?
You think
two dates is crazy?
Planning a dance
is hijinks city,
population hijinks.
Troy, I need your help.
Get some ice?
Wac...wacky ice.
The ice will be wacky.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(MUSIC IN BACKGROUND)
Thank you
for the corsage.
Oh, it matches
your carnation.
How cute.
Oh, I'm glad you like it.
I was afraid you'd think
it was old-fashioned.
I like old-fashioned.
I find it refreshing.
Speaking of refreshing,
I'm gonna get us some punch.
Be right back.
Oh!
Hi, I'm Kevin.
Apparently
I'm your DJ tonight.
Uh, I really don't know
what I'm doing, so...
If you have a request,
please be specific.
I have Changnesia.
Can I help you?
Oh, I just wanted to try on
a different look.
I'm pretty indecisive,
so I may be back here
a few times, if that's okay.
Mmm-hmm.
Cool.
I'm also gonna
need to check
this Gideon's Bible
and this jelly bean
kaleidoscope.
Icebreakers.
Mmm.
Hey, Britta.
Where's Sophie B.?
Is she backstage
drinking Zima and counting
her beanie babies?
Sorry, I can't
divulge that.
Stars and their privacy,
you know.
But she'll definitely
be here?
Oh, yeah.
Sophie be coming.
So it just be coincidence
that somebody posted
a Craigslist ad
an hour ago
that says, "Looking for
Sophie B. Hawkins,
"or convincing
Sophie B. Hawkins
impersonator
"to play community college
dance tonight.
"Very little money."
It's weird
how in demand she is.
Good thing
we booked her early.
Britta, we're running
low on chips.
Here's what I'm thinking.
I go over to the
Sadie Hawkins dance
as the snack inspector,
doing random spot checks,
and confiscate their chips.
All I need
is a disguise.
Or you could just go
to the supply closet
and get some more chips.
Okay, but I,
I still need to use
the moustache probably.
Here, in lieu of flowers
I got you this.
It's quirky.
(COCKNEY ACCENT)
Thanks, guv'nor!
I'll just put it
in me invisible sack.
Okay, I'm gonna
get us some punch.
SHIRLEY: Hey!
How are things going
with you and Jessica?
Are you two...
as they say on TV...
making a connection?
Unless that means sex,
in which case
I hope you are not.
Things are great.
Actually,
Jessica did mention
that she's cold.
Could she
borrow your sweater?
Oh.
Maybe the purple one
you wore last week.
I didn't see you
wear it home,
so I think it's still
in your locker
next to your umbrella.
I guess I could check.
Could you?
That'd be great.
Okay.
Hey, roomie.
What do you
think of Kat?
Did she tell you
she plays the saw?
I thought she was
in an all-girl kazoo band?
They need
a rhythm section, duh.
Well, keep me posted.
I'm gonna go say hi to Britta.
No, don't!
Because you have
something in your teeth.
A lot of somethings.
I do?
What is it?
Ooh, I can't tell
in this light.
But it's definitely there.
You should probably
check it out
in the bathroom.
Maybe the second floor one?
Better light.
(LIPS TIGHT) I will.
Thank you.
You're a good friend.
(PHONE VIBRATING)
(CHUCKLES)
Hello, Jeffrey.
Are you enjoying
the sock hop?
A sock hop Britta has
all but "Britta'd"
by not "Britta-ing"
her own dance.
Well, the night is young.
Mmm.
By the way,
I'm surprised
you let her share
the cafeteria with you.
Oh, I didn't want to.
But once she guaranteed
the presence of
a certain someone,
I couldn't say no.
(CHUCKLES) I wouldn't
get your hopes up for
Sophie B...
Oh, it's me.
Shall we dance? Whoop.
Are you reading
the Bible?
No spoilers.
I'm really hoping
that things turn around
for this Job guy.
So, how do I look?
Good. Except you
gotta lose the hat.
It doesn't go with
the minister's daughter.
You know what I'm doing.
Yeah.
You're on two dates at once.
I've been watching you
since you came in.
I'm not good with faces.
Is that a judgmental face
or a happy face?
I think it's awesome.
It's one of my
favorite bits,
like when a dog
acts embarrassed,
or when a guy
chases after the girl
and then
does that big public
declaration of love.
It's not realistic.
It's taking
something private
and turning it into
a performance.
Well, I think
the dog's trained.
No, I was talking about
the public declaration
of love...
Oh, you're
messing with me.
Yes, I was.
So this thing's
turning out to be a little
tougher than I thought.
You wanna help?
(SIGHS) I'd like to,
but I've still got like
1,200 pages left
of this Bible.
Yes, of course I would.
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
Tonight's Sadie Hawkins dance
is brought to you
by Hawthorne Wipes.
For the little lady
who knows her place
in the kitchen.
And tonight's
Sophie B. Hawkins dance
is brought to you
by Hawthorne Wipes.
Perfect for cleaning
the dashboard
of your '92 Subaru.
(BACKGROUND SOCK HOP MUSIC)
Ah, quite
a turnout, Britta.
Yep. Didn't know
Sophie B. Hawkins was
so big at Greendale.
Oh, yeah.
A large percentage of
Greendale students
sort of gave up
in the mid '90s,
so for many of them
Sophie B. Hawkins is
the most recent music
they're aware of.
I mean, her coming here
is gonna be a huge boost
to their spirits.
Great.
Whereas,
her not showing up
would be enough
to push these people
to such a dark place
and really question
whether life is worth
living at all.
Okay, bye-bye.
So, how long have you been
doing Bible studies?
I mean,
making miniature hats
out of duct tape?
Oh, duct tape hat...
(GASPS) Oh!
(GIBBERING) Ah!
So you've never seen any
of the  Star Wars movies?
We were taught
popular films were
the work of the devil.
Well, if you're
talking about
The Phantom Menace,
you were taught right.
Telegram.
Ooh, yeah, it's urgent.
Be right back.
Pierce,
Sophie B. Hawkins
isn't coming.
Everyone's gonna know
I'm a liar.
Help me.
Oh, Britta.
Let me tell you a story
about a friend of mine
that everyone called a liar.
His name was Bernie Madoff.
Pierce!
He was a liar.
He stole
billions of dollars
from his clients.
Has this been confirmed?
Oh, my God.
I "Britta'd" it.
Bernie?
Oh, hi, Shirley.
Hello, Annie.
Abed seems to be
having a good time,
which is all that matters.
You're right.
Looks like he made
the right choice.
He certainly did.
So, we agree.
The best woman won.
She certainly did.
He's on two dates,
isn't he?
He certainly is.
(LAUGHS)
This is the most fun
I've ever had
on a work study gig.
And I used to run
the frozen yogurt machine
before that old guy broke it.
There's been
so many close calls.
I keep forgetting details,
using the wrong names,
having to duck
behind plants.
BOTH: Aah!
This night
has been perfect.
Oh, what else
is on the list?
BOTH: Oh!
Sorry.
If this were a movie,
this would be the part
where we kiss.
You're right.
Except we're doing
a sitcom trope,
so it'd be
totally out of place.
Time to go get caught
and make an impassioned plea
to the girl I really like.
I think I'm gonna
go with Jessica.
She seems to be
the audience favorite.
Okay, bye.
Uh-oh.
Did you really think
you'd get away with this?
Let me explain.
What about
wanting to grow?
Or was that just a lie
so you could do
another world-famous
Abed TV adventure?
These are real people
you're messing with.
Kat is over there
hula-hooping
all by herself.
Abed,
in the real world
people can
actually get hurt.
Oh, this is great.
So, I got a request for,
"You suck at this.
Get off the stage."
Okay,
I don't know if that's
the band or the song.
Again, apologies.
Changnesia.
Well, it blew up
in my face,
in a slightly different way
than I planned.
Can I help you?
Where's Rachel?
She said she had to go.
Where?
I don't know.
She seemed upset.
She ran out of here
without tagging
half this stuff.
I mean,
whose water wings
are these?
(GASPS) Come back here!
Never mind.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
I know.
Sorry.
I did mean what
I said about growth.
But then
you were both so intent
on getting me dates,
I couldn't help myself.
It was wrong,
and hurtful.
I see that now.
Well, maybe
setting you up
was a bad idea.
Yeah, I guess
neither of our girls were
really right for you.
The worst part is that
I met a girl tonight
that I really do like.
But I was so busy
chasing one trope,
I missed the trope
right under my nose...
That the girl
I liked all along
was under my nose.
And now
I've screwed things up.
I don't know if I can
make them right.
BOTH: Aw!
Wait.
This one's real, right?
Yeah, I'm really sad.
BOTH: Aw!
Well, go find her, dummy.
Yeah, haven't you ever
seen a movie?
ALL: Sophie! Sophie! Sophie!
Sophie. Sophie. Sophie.
I hate to say
I told you so,
but I'm gonna say it
to Britta's face.
ALL: Sophie! Sophie! Sophie!
What is the nature of hope?
Sophie's not coming, guys.
(ALL BOOING)
Boo! Boo!
Looks like someone
underestimated
the time it takes
to plan a dance.
(ALL BOOING)
Hey, hey, hey!
It's Sophie B. Hawkins!
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC)
(APPLAUSE)
(CHEERING)
Good evening!
I'm Sophie B. Hawkins.
I think
you know this one.
Oh, man.
(PLAYING  DAMN I WISH
I WAS YOUR LOVER)
♪ That old dog has chained
you up all right
♪ Give you everything
you need
♪ To live inside
a twisted cage
♪ Sleep beside an empty rage
Did you do this?
If it's possible
to make something happen
by willing it,
then, yes, I did.
♪ Damn, I wish
I was your lover
♪ I'd rock you till
the daylight comes
♪ Made sure you are smiling
and warm
♪ I am everything
♪ Tonight I'll be your mother
♪ I'll do such things
to ease your pain
♪ Free your mind
and you won't feel ashamed
♪ Oh ♪
Pardon me, Sophie.
(FEEDBACK)
I have something to say.
(CROWD GRUMBLES)
There was a girl here tonight.
Her name was Rachel.
I met her,
and it was very pleasant.
And I made a mistake.
And now I'd very much
like to continue this
conversation in private.
SOPHIE:  Wow, viva lost love.
(CHEERING)
(MUSIC RESTARTS)
♪ Damn
♪ I wish I was your lover
♪ I'd rock you till
the daylight comes... ♪
You came back.
That was pretty
embarrassing.
I had to... (LAUGHS)
Hmm.
It was.
But I'm glad I did it.
So, would you like
to go out sometime?
I would like that.
Do you want
to pretend like you're
just going out with me
on a bet?
Oh, I'd like that very much.
Mmm-hmm.
But maybe we should
try normal first.
Sure.
BOTH: Aw!
I prefer  As I Lay Me Down.
Me too.
I can't believe
she pulled this off.
I know.
According to dean law,
I must now give her
my amulet.
What?
Hmm?
Well, she had
a little help from
a wise old man
who was the
official supplier of
Moist Towelette
to the Lilith Fair between
1997 and 1999.
I knew it.
You're safe.
You did this?
But why?
Because, in the face
of all logic and reason,
Britta didn't back down.
That makes no sense.
Also, I didn't
like the way
you were being
such a jerk to her.
Well, she was acting crazy.
Yeah, but what choice
did she have?
You make fun of her,
you use her name
as a synonym
for screwing up.
Cut her some
slack, Jeff.
(CHEERING)
She helped you reconcile
with your dad.
For Pete's sake,
let her be happy.
(SOPHIE HAWKINS'S
AS I LAY ME DOWN)
♪ It felt like springtime
on this February morning
♪ In the courtyard birds
were singing your praise
"I know it's probably
impossible to read my texts
"without them sounding
sarcastic,
"but I assure you,
"this one is as earnest
as they come.
"Congratulations on
an awesome dance.
"You Britta'd the hell
out of this thing."
♪ This I pray
♪ That you will hold me, dear
♪ As I lay me down to sleep
♪ This I pray
♪ That you will
hold me, dear
♪ Though I'm far away
♪ I'll whisper your name
♪ Into the sky
Can you do one
where you wish
you had ice cream?
♪ Damn, I wish
I had some ice cream ♪
Ah!
So good!
Okay, can you do one
where you wish
I was Batman?
Fine, but this is
the last one.
Okay.
♪ Damn, I wish Abed
was Batman
Ah, it's just so good!
I love it so much!
All right, all right.
You guys are taking advantage
of Mrs. B. Hawkins.
No, but...but...
But...but...
But you nothing,
she's an artist.
She is not here
to do your bidding.
Sorry about that.
Now, if you could
just sing
"Dean, I wish
I was your lover"
with these new lyrics.
It's for my voicemail.
Who's Jeff Winger?
Just sing the damn song.