[♪♪♪]
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up
Tied up, dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪
Okay, this awkward silence
has been going on for days.
Granted, Jeffrey looks
amazing when he broods,
but this has got to stop.
Now, I don't know
what happened,
but we have to get
to the bottom of this.
It's too embarrassing.
I understand.
You don't wanna talk about it,
and you won't have to.
They will talk for you.
Why did you make, have,
and bring these?
Don't answer.
It's puppet therapy.
Mm-hmm.
The psychology world
has recently embraced it
after seeing it on Law &amp; Order.
You'll notice that each puppet
is made in your likeness.
They were a rush job.
It's not like I had them
on hand for personal use.
[CHUCKLES]
Excuse me.
Let me just grab this thing
that's definitely not a whip.
In addition
to being adorable,
I know firsthand
that puppet therapy
can and does work.
Uh, Dean,
puppet Kevin here thinks
I should have a candy bar
right now.
No, you know
how it winds you up.
[HIGH VOICE]
Fine. We'll split it.
[NORMAL VOICE]
All right. Got money, bro?
[HIGH VOICE]
He's not what he seems!
Wait.
Where's Pierce?
I know he's not with us,
but is he still with us?
I'm sure he's fine.
Although no one's seen him
since he lost his mind
in the woods.
You all were
in the woods? Oh.
Oh, so the puppets
are working. Okay.
Uh... Ha, ha.
How did it start?
What happened?
We're not playing with puppets.
Oh, Jeffrey.
Dean, what happened
is between us and Jesus,
and Jesus
don't snitch.
Yeah, and I don't need
a puppet to express myself.
I already say
whatever I want.
But I am a fan
of the medium, so...
My father
is withholding.
Ow.
Hmm. That's interesting.
Guys, are we just gonna avoid
making eye contact forever?
Who are we, Jeff during sex?
BOTH: Huh?
Let's just give it a shot
and move on.
Fine. If we're gonna
play this game,
then unlike sex with Britta,
we're gonna do it quickly
and with a small shred
of dignity.
Eh.
Yeah.
Jeffrey,
dignity is my middle name,
and my first name is...
Dean-nocchio!
[MIMICS GRAND ENTRANCE MUSIC]
Whoo.
It all started
on Friday.
Britta was talking about
a few of her latest causes.
This one's for
the Greendale animal shelter,
this one's for global warming,
this one's for global cooling--
And this one's for
the amount of rubber wasted
while making
stupid bracelets.
That's called rubber flubbing,
and it's a real problem.
Open your eyes, people!
Britta said, "Open your eyes,
people." Square.
Nice.
What are you two doing?
Oh. Playing Study Group Bingo.
Study Group Bingo?
We've been best friends
for four years,
so we've fallen into
a comfortable pattern
like humorous misunderstandings
on Three's Company
or girls gossiping
on Gossip Girl.
So to liven things up, Troy
and I made this bingo chart
of the predictable things
we say.
This game is gay.
Square.
You're mocking us?
That's not a very
Christian thing to do.
Square.
Can we go back to studying now?
BOTH: Square.
I don't like this game.
Me neither.
I think it's mean.
There's no point.
Yeah, it's insulting.
Okay, stop.
ALL: Square.
Ugh. Abed's right.
We've had the same
conversation a million times.
I guess we're kind of
stuck in a...
ALL: Rut?
Yes.
But to be fair, there's not many
things you could be stuck in.
Elevators.
Bad marriages.
A peat bog.
On a flight in the middle seat.
Time loops.
The bottom of a well.
Your own emotions.
Quicksand.
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
[EXHALES]
Okay, stop!
ALL: Square.
How did we get
so predictable?
And here is our state-of-the-art
1989 library, where...
Oh, look! It is
my favorite study group.
They all really typify
the diversity we have here
at Greendale.
Uh, ruggedly handsome
leading man...
Heh, heh.
A mom, an activist,
a perfect student,
a lifelong learner,
a sidekick, and Abed.
Enough foreplay. It's time
to move this tour along
to meet my good friend
Magnitude!
Yeah, prepare
to be pop-popped!
MAN:
Aw, he's a national treasure.
Look, the problem isn't us.
We're awesome.
The problem
is Greendale.
It's pulling our strings,
and we need a break.
Yeah, our Ferris Bueller
needs a day off.
Hey, whose dad
has a vintage Ferrari?
Abed, a pop culture reference
is more of the same.
We need to go big.
We need an adventure!
That's a good idea, Annie,
but there's one problem.
Where would we go?
[♪♪♪]
♪ Where, where
Would we go? ♪
♪ We can go anywhere
That you know ♪
BOTH:
♪ Could we travel
Through time? ♪
♪ Or maybe see France? ♪
♪ Or anywhere else
Naked ladies will dance? ♪
♪ Could we fly
In a booth ♪
♪ Could we go
To church camp? ♪
♪ I'd rather stay
At Greendale ♪
♪ Could we ride ♪
♪ A hot air balloon? ♪
ALL: ♪ Yes ♪
♪ Now, that's an adventure ♪
♪ We should go soon ♪
♪ We can go anywhere
In a balloon ♪
ALL: ♪ Yes ♪
♪ That's an adventure ♪
♪ We can go high ♪
♪ We can see anything
Up in the sky ♪
ALL:
♪ Yes, now
That's an adventure ♪
♪ Pierce
bring your dentures ♪
ALL:
♪ We're so thrilled
Because soon ♪
♪ We'll be
In a hot air balloon ♪
ALL:
♪ Ah, ah, ah ♪
Hey, guys.
♪ I'm the balloon guide ♪
♪ Before we take off, I'm
Gonna check the balloon ties ♪
♪ Look at the burner
Check out the basket ♪
♪ If you have a question
Feel free to ask it ♪
♪ Could we go to space? ♪
♪ Could we fly to heaven? ♪
♪ I'd rather fly to Vegas ♪
♪ It's getting time ♪
♪ To ride the balloon ♪
ALL:
♪ Yes, now, this is adventure ♪
♪ About to go soon ♪
♪ We're gonna go anywhere
In the balloon ♪
♪ Yes, this is adventure ♪
♪ We're starting to fly ♪
♪ We can see everything
Here in the sky ♪
♪ This is adventure ♪
♪ There's beautiful weather
Now outside ♪
♪ And we're fine ♪
♪ As long as we have
A balloon guide ♪
Uh...
Oh, no!
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
ABED:
Oh, boy.
From now on, no more
singing in the balloon.
Did I miss it?
Miss what?
Who said anything
about a runaway balloon?
Okay, let me process this.
[STRAINED INHALE]
No!
Oh, God.
Whoa, whoa.
We're really high.
PIERCE: I'm scared of heights.
Guys, what are we gonna do?
ANNIE:
I had a dream
it would end this way.
Oh, Jeffrey, you're
on a runaway balloon?
You could have died.
How could you
almost let him die?
We all almost died,
but we all didn't.
Plus, a near-death experience
would've only brought us
closer together.
Good point.
Although it did get
pretty hairy after that,
especially once Pierce
started helping.
PIERCE:
Okay, everyone push down
with me at the same time.
One, two, three!
[GROANS]
Come on, people.
I can't do this alone.
You can't do it at all.
[GROANS]
Oh, look.
A downstream.
[GASPS]
ALL: Pierce! No!
Whoa!
TROY:
If we fly to heaven,
please don't tell my grandpa
about me and Britta.
[INDISTINCT DIALOGUE]
SHIRLEY:
We're so high.
JEFF:
This is not good.
There are so many clouds.
It's so dark!
I can't even see
the Landing Strip
or any of the other
nudie bars.
Oh, heaven, help us.
We must be a mile
above the ground.
That's international airspace.
We're literally
above the law.
Jeff can marry any man he wants.
Wait a second, guys.
I think we're starting
to go down.
You see?
Prayer works.
So does gravity, Shirley.
And you know who invented
gravity, right?
ALL:
Oh! Whoa!
Guys, let's put a pin
in the mysteries of the universe
convo until we land.
Which will be sooner
than we thought.
We're gaining speed fast,
people. Oh! Brace for impact.
Oh, damn you, gravity!
Damn you, prayer!
Damn you, Vicki!
[ALL SCREAM]
Has anyone else noticed
Professor Duncan
hasn't been around
for a long time?
[ALL SCREAM]
[♪♪♪]
Maybe I can soften
our descent.
Pierce, no!
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
BRITTA:
Bring it to me strong,
old man monkey strength!
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
[BIRD CHIRPS]
SHIRLEY:
Okay.
Okay, obviously,
that was very scary.
Post-traumatic stress
is a real issue,
but with these puppets
giving voice to our feelings,
we can begin to heal.
Hey, come on.
This is gonna be
a long and arduous process.
There's more.
Hey, well, excuse Dean
for reacting to the natural
lull in your story.
I'm so sorry.
When you hurt,
I hurt.
[SIGHS]
What happened next?
ABED: Whoa.
[SHIRLEY SIGHS]
SHIRLEY: We made it.
BRITTA: Everyone okay?
PIERCE: I'm alive.
BOTH: Square.
Guys, knock it off.
Okay, still alive?
Okay, we're all safe.
We just have to figure out
how to get back to Greendale.
But we're in the middle
of the woods.
Where do we start?
We need to split
into two groups,
the survivors and the others.
Where's the manifest?
Oh, stop it with
your Lost references.
We need to
get back home.
What if we're
stuck here?
We need to start
a prison system.
We'll be stranded
here forever,
and I've never seen
Blue Man Group!
Guys, guys, we're gonna
make it outta here.
We gotta relax.
We're all gonna be fine.
[GROANS]
ALL: Aah!
What is that?
I just want to say,
if we're gonna die,
I love you guys.
I love you all too.
I did see Blue Man Group.
I just didn't get it.
Why can't they talk?
They have so much in common.
[GROANING
AND NERVOUS SIGHING]
[HISSES]
Others!
Huh?
[HISSES]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Oh!
[LAUGHS]
I'm sorry.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I didn't mean
to startle anybody. Heh.
And I thought my hair
looked fake.
Oh, you guys are a long,
long way from Greendale.
How did you know
we're from Greendale?
Oh, from Pierce's shirt.
How did you know
my name is Pierce?
It's embroidered
on your Greendale shirt
you got
at the student store.
How'd you know I got it
at the student store?
I'm a touch psychic.
ALL: Oh. Huh. Hmm.
Anyway, I used to go
to Greendale just like you guys
before I came out here
to be free.
So this is how Greendale
graduates end up...
as transient mountain men.
Huh.
Not as bad as I thought.
But don't you miss
having stuff?
Out here, you have
everything you need.
And you can be
whoever you wanna be.
ALL:
Huh. Oh.
♪ Here in the woods ♪
♪ You're totally free ♪
♪ You can live off the land ♪
♪ And be who you want to be ♪
BOTH:
♪ We can be our own men ♪
♪ And I don't need an A ♪
♪ The perfect mom pressure
Would all go away ♪
♪ Greendale is crazy ♪
♪ And so is that moose ♪
Hi, Troy.
♪ Greendale turns
People's screws so loose ♪
♪ We're no exception
To tell you the truth ♪
♪ Which is why the woods
Is perfect ♪
♪ For all of you ♪
♪ Being socially conscious
Can be really tough ♪
♪ Ah, here in the woods ♪
♪ You can forget
All that stuff ♪
♪ I don't like the pressure ♪
♪ To always be cool ♪
♪ I was gonna
Sing that ♪
♪ Now I don't have
A rhyme ♪
♪ We all try our hardest ♪
♪ But the pressure in college ♪
SHIRLEY:
♪ Sometimes gets
so tremendous ♪
♪ That it would be
Stupendous ♪
ANNIE:
♪ To be free ♪
♪ Far away ♪
BOTH:
♪ From Greendale ♪
Mmm, ooh, yummy.
♪ I really love
These berries ♪
♪ Where are they from? ♪
♪ My hand just made
A rainbow ♪
♪ And my... ♪
♪ Magic, magic ♪
♪ Well, these magical berries ♪
♪ Put us in a drug sequence ♪
SHIRLEY:
♪ They make
Everything swirly ♪
♪ Whoa, that bush
Sounds like Shirley ♪
ALL:
♪ Now, we're free ♪
♪ Far away ♪
♪ From Greendale ♪
Be free, my friends.
Be free.
[SIGHING]
Simply inspiring.
Ten minutes ago,
you weren't even speaking.
And now, you've admitted
that a strange man
hand-fed you
psychotropic berries.
This is
puppet therapy work...
Dean! There is a fire
in the cafeteria.
Garrett, not now!
Ohh. Ha, ha.
Where was I?
Ah! I was healing you.
Hmm?
Go on.
Well, those devil berries
freed our minds
and loosened our tongues.
[♪♪♪]
Your skin
is so beautiful
and soft.
It's like felt.
[OVERLAPPING RELAXED
DIALOGUE AND SIGHING]
I feel so free out here,
like I'm my own man.
If Jeff said
we had to live out here,
I'd totally be
down with that.
[SIGHING]
Me too.
Can I tell you guys
a secret?
Yeah, sure.
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
I was at the grocery store
with my kids,
and I thought I saw Andre
walk by with another woman.
I love women.
Mmm.
[SIGHS]
I'm gonna go take
a growler.
Anyway, I wanted to follow
Andre and the woman,
so I left my kids
at the magazine stand
for just a minute,
but somehow
I lost track of time
and ended up tailing them
all the way out of town.
It wasn't even Andre.
The horrible part is
I forgot my kids
and left them all night
in the grocery store.
[♪♪♪]
Well, there y'all go,
giving me that look,
treating me like Judas,
judging me like Judy.
You know, Judge Judy.
She judges people.
Shirley, this is the first
I've heard of you
leaving your kids
in a grocery store.
Me too. I have no memory
of you saying that.
Well, if you don't know
my secret,
why have we all been
so awkward around each other?
I thought everyone heard
my secret.
I didn't hear
you say anything.
So nobody else heard
my terrible secret
about how I...
trail off
from time to time?
Did everyone here
reveal a secret?
ALL: Mm-hmm.
And no one remembers
anyone else's, including mine?
ALL: Mm-mmm.
Those berries made us real
talky, but not real listen-y.
So if no one heard
or remembers
anything anyone else said...
We're in the clear.
♪ We're in the clear ♪
I'm a genius!
Yeah!
♪ We're in the clear ♪
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
Um, guys?
[♪♪♪]
Well, um,
don't mind me.
I'm sure you guys can
get on with your lives
without the worst mom ever.
[EXHALES]
Sounds good.
Anyone up for a movie?
Abed, sit.
Shirley, you have nothing
to be ashamed of.
No one thinks
you're a bad mom.
Thanks, Jeff, but I'm...
I'm just gonna go home now.
Shirley, wait.
I think I know how to make you
feel a little less horrible.
BRITTA:
I like where you're headed.
Okay, who's holding?
I have four berries,
but I am saving them
for Laser Floyd.
No, we all need to re-share
our secrets sober.
Oh, God.
Look,
we were all feeling
crappy earlier,
but at least we were
feeling crappy together.
Shirley is alone now.
This is the only way
to put us on equal footing,
and if it makes it
any easier,
we can use these puppets.
Ah, yay!
Shut up.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
I found the perfect girl
for me,
and then I met her kid.
♪ I said
It didn't bother me ♪
♪ But truthfully it did ♪
♪ I promised him
I'd make it ♪
♪ To a baseball game he had ♪
♪ But I bailed
And never called again ♪
♪ And now I'm just
Exactly like my dad ♪
♪ I am an activist ♪
♪ That's always been
My choice ♪
♪ Truth is
I've never voted ♪
♪ Except when I watch
The Voice ♪
♪ I was struggling
In History ♪
♪ I'm normally the best ♪
♪ I let Cornwallis
Rub my feet ♪
♪ To give me
All the answers to a test ♪
♪ I caused ♪
♪ The Greendale ♪
♪ Fire of '03 ♪
♪ Fifty-five acres ♪
♪ Went up in a blaze ♪
♪ All because I burned
An ant hill ♪
ALL:
♪ This secret inside me ♪
♪ Was trapped
Beyond a doubt ♪
♪ And now my most terrible ♪
♪ Secret's out ♪
There you are.
Come on, guys.
♪ I've never slept
With the great Eartha Kitt ♪
♪ We dry humped
Inside of her tour bus ♪
ALL:
♪ This secret inside me ♪
♪ Was trapped
Beyond a doubt ♪
♪ And now my most terrible ♪
♪ Secret's out ♪
[EXHALES]
I wanna thank you all
for being so open and honest
and for syncing
your mouth and hand movements.
And now, for my most
terrible secret.
I am not what you would
call traditionally--
Wait, Abed, you never
told us your secret.
That's right.
I didn't share one that night.
After we got back
from the woods,
everyone was being silent
and not making eye contact.
I didn't know why,
so I mirrored your behavior.
BOTH: Oh...
Mmm.
[GIGGLES]
Thank you, Jeff,
and I don't think you're
anything like your father.
I don't know how
you take care of one kid,
let alone three.
Aw. That's nice.
So nobody thinks
I'm a slutty cheater?
ALL:
No.
Or me as a criminal?
ALL: No.
Nobody respects me any less as
a political activist, right?
Well, uh...
The level
to which we respect you
as a political activist
has definitely not changed.
That's right.
That's how I would say it.
Exactly.
Whew.
Bye, Dean.
Bye-bye.
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
ABED:
Knowledge is a party.
Once again, I help fix
everyone's problems,
only to go home alone.
PUPPET JEFF: [SEDUCTIVELY]
Who says you have
to be alone?
Jeffrey.
[ABED HUMMING]
[SCATTING]
[BEATBOXING]
[HUMMING]
Yeah!