Come on, guys.
I got class in 15 minutes.
This should not be
that difficult.
We just need to figure out
an idea for our final
history project.
What we need
to figure out
is Greendale's obsession
with group assignments.
(SCOFFS)
Classic herd mentality.
All right,
Britta doesn't have one.
Who else?
I've been told
I look like a Kennedy.
Nope, not an idea.
That's a statement.
Anyone not on medication?
Jeff, we have
to take this seriously.
This assignment?
This, we have
to take seriously?
"Pick any moment
from history
and tell me about it.
"Be as creative as you want.
Or not. I don't care.
"Professor Cornwaaa..."
He didn't even finish
signing his name.
Okay, yes,
he phoned this one in
but my run at valedictorian
is in jeopardy.
As is mine.
As is Shirley's.
And I just took one
for the team
by accepting that C+
on our last history paper.
As did I.
As did Shirley.
So I'd think you'd want
to rise to the occasion
and help get me
back on top.
Or me.
Shirley, I'm speaking
for both you and me.
Then, you might want to teach
your mouth how to say
"we," "our," and "us."
I've been told
I look like a Kennedy.
Nope, still just
a random statement,
and still useless.
Okay.
How about this?
We do a series of banners...
Great, it's settled.
You don't even know
what I'm going to say!
Don't need to.
Tomorrow is Friday,
and I have no intention
of being here late.
Your banner thing
sounds doable.
And this assignment?
Passable, so passable.
And passable
assures my graduation,
so we are doing doable
and passable.
Uh, speaking of tomorrow,
Troy and Britta,
have you decided what
you're gonna do for
your one-year anniversary?
BOTH: Of?
Your first date?
Oh! Yeah! (SCOFFS)
Da-doy.
That was a test,
and you failed.
I was just kidding.
You guys are dating?
Man!
Somebody's sure
working her way
around the table.
Aren't you?
Well, you should really
do something special.
Something romantic.
Mmm-hmm.
Like go back
to  Senor Kevin's for lunch,
where it all began.
(GIGGLES)
Yeah, sure.
We could do that.
Sure,
that sounds fun.
Speaking of anniversaries,
it is the third anniversary
of me and Abed
watching  Freaky Friday
for the first time.
BOTH: Oh!
That, you remember?
Movie Trolley is having
an "end of the video store
chain industry" sale,
so I got you a six-pack
of body switching movies
and a two-year-old box
of Raisinets,
all for under five bucks.
Whoo!
All right, man.
Change Up.
13 Going On 30,
17 Again, 18 Again,
Vice Versa...
(SHIRLEY GASPS)
Judge Reinhold.
BOTH: Oh.
Freaky Friday.
(STILTED) Oh, Troy,
you are so thoughtful.
I wish I had the capacity
for sentimentality
like you do.
(STILTED) Me?
I wish I was more like you.
No emotional hang-ups,
endless cool adventures.
You have it so easy.
No, you do, Troy.
No, you do, Abed.
BOTH: I wish I could
switch places with you
for just one day!
(BABBLING GIBBERISH)
BOTH: Ah!
Oh.
Sorry. Routine
light switch check.
(SIGHS) Oh.
(SIGHS) I thought
that would work.
Yeah, we're all floored
it didn't.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
Mmm. Good morning.
Oh, and, um...
Happy one-year
anniversary.
(DIRECT, AS ABED)
Yes. That would be this day.
Look, I know that
it was awkward yesterday.
They pointed it out
and we didn't remember
but... (SCOFFS)
that doesn't mean
that we should
feel pressure
to make some big deal
out of it, right?
No, I'm looking
forward to it.
Super looking
I'm just saying...
Yeah.
Same page.
Excuse me.
Hey, buddy, wake up!
Remember yesterday,
when we faked a body switching
thing and it didn't work?
Well, now,
it's actually worked.
So, right now...
I'm you and you're me.
(EMOTING, AS TROY)
Oh, my God. This is
wrinkling my brain!
And of all the days!
I got my big,
important meeting
with my study group.
Me too. Oh, boy.
Here goes nothing.
Hmm.
Huh.
Okay,
so we're telling the story
of the American Revolution
through banners.
Everyone is responsible
for one.
To maximize efficiency,
I've designated areas:
Colored pencils and markers,
paints, puffy paint...
Yes,
there's a difference.
Decoupage and glitter and...
This is the approval station,
where Shirley and I
will decide whether
you have to start over or not.
Annie, remember.
We're doing doable
and passable.
We're doing
whatever it takes
to help us...
Thank you.
...beat Leonard.
Wait, Leonard is now
the front runner
for valedictorian?
You're getting beat
by Leonard?
(CHUCKLES)
He's so old.
All right.
Yes, we slipped
below Leonard,
but Annie and I are
a close three and two,
respectively.
(LOW)
Annie is the three.
That is what
"respectively" suggests.
(MUMBLING)
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm.
(CHUCKLES) Whoa!
That was weird.
Mmm-hmm.
We didn't mean to do that.
We know exactly where we sit.
Um, what's going on
with you guys?
BOTH:
Oh, thank God,
you noticed.
Remember when
we pretended to
switch bodies yesterday?
Unfortunately,
yes, dorks.
Well, it really happened.
I'm actually Abed.
And I'm actually Troy.
All right.
I don't care who's who.
We're all here,
and that's all I need
to complete
this passable project
in a doable amount of time.
Wish we could help, Jeff,
but in order to switch back,
we have to recreate
the exact moment
that all this happened,
but the DVD is missing.
Of course it is.
So now,
I have to find it
while Troy goes on
an anniversary date
with Britta.
What?
(MIMICS GUNSHOT)
Oh, hey.
Here's a fun sci-fi thing.
How about you make
a banner as Troy
and you make
a banner as Abed,
and we'll be done
within the hour.
Uh, per banner,
if we're lucky.
And that's
if we want an A.
Okay, you two
need to let go
of the pressure
you're putting
on this project
to get an A.
BOTH: I deserve
to be number one!
Sorry. Or me!
Sorry.
I have to go talk to Troy.
Yes, please.
Tell your boyfriend
and his boyfriend
that playtime is over.
Annie, Shirley, go find out
what's keeping Leonard on top.
And Abed won't switch back
until we get that DVD.
I'll deal with that.
And then,
we are meeting back here
and getting up
into some puffy paint
and doing our doable,
passable banners!
What do you want me
to do?
Stay alive.
Or don't.
I'm on it.
Wait, Troy!
I'm Abed.
Oh, right.
Uh, "Troy," could you
please excuse us?
You were weird this morning,
and now, well, weirder.
Are we still on
for  Senor Kevin's
or are you guys doing
this whole switchy thing?
Actually, he's kind of
going through some stuff.
Oh.
Is he having some issues
that he's having trouble
dealing with?
Yeah, he kind of needs this,
so he's really laying into it.
Oh, so he might need
an almost therapist.
Perhaps I'll pencil him in
for a session,
you know,
after my date with Troy.
See you later, Abed.
Dean, I need you.
(GASPS) It's happening.
Shut the door.
What?
Hmm?
Dean, I need you
to give this DVD
to Troy and Abed.
Oh, I love those movies!
They should make more of them.
They're a timeless tale.
Why can't you
give it to them?
Troy and Abed think
they switched bodies
while holding
onto a  Freaky Friday DVD,
which, of course,
is now mysteriously missing,
and they can't switch back
until they find it.
Now, I'd give them
this one myself,
but they'll think
that I bought it,
which I did.
Wait.
How did they switch bodies?
(SCOFFS) Well, they held
onto the DVD and said...
BOTH: I wish I could
switch places with you
for just one day.
Oh! Oh!
Ah! (GASPS)
Sorry. Routine
light switch check.
That is not a thing!
What?
(DEEP, AS JEFF)
Oh, you've got
to be kidding me.
I'm you?
What?
No! You're not.
Of course.
It's fricking Friday.
There's no justification
to be made,
because it can't happen,
weirdo.
Whatever, Dean.
Now, please leave your office
so I can start
to work on your weird body
that I'm now stuck in!
You're not even
holding a phone!
So, Troy,
how's Abed coping?
I mean,
with his day in your body?
You'd have to ask him.
I, for one, am freaked.
Look at his arms and legs.
He's like
the pick-up sticks
of people.
Do you think he's trying
to hide from something
he's not understanding?
If you're worried about Abed,
you should talk to him.
Right.
I should talk to him.
Well, well, well.
John McLame.
Never thought
I'd see your face again.
Back for more, huh?
I'm sorry,
back for what?
Punishment.
Last time I saw you,
you got your panties
all in a wad
'cause I said  Die Hard
was a suckfest of a movie.
(FORCED) Wait, what?
You hate  Die Hard?
That sounds insane to me.
It is,
without a doubt,
the most unnecessary movie
ever made.
I'm not who you think
I am, man.
What else do you hate
about the movie?
'Cause I would love to hear
all of your opinions.
(LAUGHING) Well, I mean,
where to even start?
It's riddled with plot holes.
There's no logic to it.
I would rather
watch a napkin sit
and do nothing all day
than to even
endure the trailer
for  Die Hard!
Wow, that's hatred.
Babe, we should order.
I'm both starving
and another word
for wanting food.
Troy!
Oh, thank God,
you've come to your senses.
You answered to Troy.
We're in public.
I have to. I'm Abed.
Of course you are.
Well, Abed, I found the DVD.
You can switch back now.
(CHUCKLES) Nice try.
That's the remake.
In the original,
the mom and daughter
simply exclaimed,
"I wish I could
switch places with you
for just one day."
Like we did.
In that one,
there's a magic
fortune cookie.
Oh, I always wondered
what the differences were.
Listen, why don't
I pitch you a remake
of a remake,
where my magic mouth
tells you drop the act
because Abed
isn't even here.
Then, you cough up the DVD
and we go tell Abed
you're back
in your own bodies,
so we can go do doable
and passable banners.
First,
that's a terrible movie.
Second, I understand
why you're frustrated,
it's in your nature,
but this is happening.
This happened.
So, unless we find
that DVD...
Oh, no,
let's go find this DVD.
By all means,
let's waste more
of my life.
Now, we were the last ones
to leave the study room
last night.
Maybe one of
the janitors took it.
Great.
Let's go find that janitor.
Maybe you can
switch bodies with him,
or maybe
with his magic mop...
Stop pitching.
It's not your thing.
You're right,
that's ridiculous,
unlike what we're doing.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Dean?
Yeah, come in.
I'd stop what I'm doing,
but then I'd be
depriving you of the view.
You're welcome.
What's up?
Um, is this a bad time?
Uh, I'm in Greendale,
stuck in the body
of a man who could be
Gollum's shadow,
so yeah,
I'd say it's half past suck.
(LAUGHS) Totally.
"Half past suck."
That's funny.
Okay.
That's creepy.
Uh, Dean.
We're losing to Leonard
in the race of valedictorian,
and we were wondering
if we could take a peek
at his transcripts to see
how that is even possible.
Are you serious?
Mmm.
You mean
put my integrity
on the line?
You want me
to jeopardize
the very reputation
of this school
that I've spent
so long protecting?
You're right.
We're sorry.
And that is what
I would be saying
if I gave a crap.
Awesome!
Ah, here's the answer.
Back in 1968,
Leonard got an A in
rotary phone maintenance.
Since then, he's been taking
every other class pass/fail
to keep a perfect GPA.
Well, what does this mean?
It means we're taking
an old man down.
(GASPS) Ooh.
You're welcome.
What is wrong with you?
I don't know.
How's your bean burrito?
Good. Thank you
for ordering for me.
I know
what you always get.
Yeah, you know me so well.
I know a lot about you.
I know you grind
your teeth at night,
it keeps me up.
I know about your tattoo.
Which one?
The Greenpeace one
you haven't gotten yet
because you're afraid
of needles.
Did Troy tell you
these things?
I am Troy.
Well,
it must upset Abed
to hear all of this
relationship talk.
He doesn't seem to care.
Maybe.
But maybe he doesn't like
talking to you about us.
I could see that
causing him to act out.
Nah, I don't see that.
I don't think
he's that invested in us.
But he talks to you
about us.
I talk to him.
What do you say
when you talk to him
about us?
Do you tell him
that things are good?
I don't know.
Are they?
Well, what you think?
Well...
I guess I wonder
why we didn't
remember our anniversary.
Not everybody's Annie.
No, but I don't know.
Seems like, you know,
that would be special to us,
like, especially
if things were good.
Something we'd want
to celebrate.
Well, we are.
Are we?
(LAUGHTER)
Yes, Lord Brickell,
I was indeed
down by the stables.
Damn, man.
You ever heard of knocking?
Yup, just heard it,
when I did it a second ago.
They've seen too much!
Let's kill them!
Stand down,
Crazy Schmidt.
What we're doing here
is none of their business.
We're having
Murder Mystery Night
during the day.
I was fine with
"none of your business."
We're looking
for a  Freaky Friday DVD.
Oh, I love those movies.
They should make
more of those...
Nope. We left it
in study room "F"
last night.
Well, everything we find
goes straight to
the Lost and Found.
Great, show us.
And the "wasting my life" tour
continues.
Leonard!
We just looked
at your transcript.
I knew this day would come.
I'm outta here.
There you go.
My work here is done.
You're one and two again.
Now, you can direct
your anger and
resentment at each other.
Congrats.
Classic wrap-up.
Shut up, Leonard!
I've got a picture
of your old nose!
It was a lateral move!
Dean!
(TURNED ON) Dean.
Annie.
Why is this happening?
Holy Makes-Complete-
Sense-At-This-School!
FYI, one of these piles
is load-bearing,
so, uh, yeah,
watch that.
Jeez.
This is gonna be harder
than I thought.
This DVD isn't
gonna find itself.
And neither are we, Troy,
because it's not in here,
and you know that.
This is dumb.
Why are you
so committed to this bit?
If you're really
a friend to Abed, to me,
then you'll end it, now.
Sorry.
I have to keep
going, for Troy.
You don't have
to dig through
all this stuff. I will.
I know
it isn't your problem.
I'm just glad I'm here.
This is the sweeter end
of the deal.
Troy still has to go
on his date with Britta.
I don't understand
this whole relationship thing
or why Troy would even
want to be in one.
How long have you
felt this way?
Or at least,
how long have you
been talking to Abed
about this?
Not that long.
It's more lately,
I guess.
It's felt different,
like we're working at it
too hard.
And he doesn't think
it should be.
It should be easy,
but he says it isn't.
It feels like
we're just going
through the motions.
Because he's afraid
if he doesn't, it just ends.
Then what?
What if they're not
friends anymore?
He'd hate that.
He'd hate himself.
I don't want to lose
what we had.
So he's here,
at this point,
not knowing
how to talk to her,
not knowing how to tell her
that he wants to break up.
Wait, are you
breaking up with me?
I think so?
I'm sorry, Jeff.
I shouldn't have
brought you down here,
into any of this.
Especially for a bit.
I know you don't
respect them.
That's true. They're dumb,
and I stand by that,
but committing to them isn't.
I wish I had the courage
to commit to a bit
like you, Abed,
or to a relationship,
like Troy.
Committing is hard,
because we're all scared
of what happens
when we find out
we committed
to the wrong thing,
but there's no shame
in what Troy's done.
He put himself out there
and he really tried,
and that proves he cares.
That said,
and as hard
as it may seem,
right now, Troy needs
to show he cares.
He needs to put
himself out there
and own how he feels.
That proves he's a man.
So...
Yeah, I don't think
this is the way
either of us
thought this would go.
No, I can't say
that I did.
I mean, not this,
not us here.
(SIGHS)
But I can say that
whenever you guys switch back
to your original bodies,
I want to thank Abed
for being such a good friend
to both of us.
Troy, wait.
Don't do it like this.
I understand why
you had to go high concept,
because you're scared,
but Britta deserves better.
Troy, it's time.
BOTH: I wish
I had my own body back!
(BABBLING GIBBERISH)
Sorry, routine
light switch check.
(BABBLING CONTINUES)
Oh.
Hmm.
Oh, I've been meaning
to see this.
First, the easiest part,
because it's the most obvious.
I'm sorry.
I think I proved today
that I'm not ready for this.
I wanted it to work.
I did.
I care about you so much,
and I love
being around you.
I just think I'm better
as your friend,
because that I know
I can be good at.
So I'm number two again,
which is what it is.
But, you know,
if I'm not going
to be valedictorian,
I'm glad it will be you.
Mmm, me too.
You mean,
you hope it's me
if it's not you,
or that you're glad
it's you?
Yes.
Thanks for everything
you did for me today.
I'm sorry
I pulled you into it.
That was my problem,
not yours.
It's the best way
someone's ever
woken me up in my life.
How was lunch?
It was good.
It really was.
I'll tell you
about it later.
Oh, there you are.
I got bored waiting,
so I went ahead
and did our whole project.
(CHUCKLES)
Pierce, no offense,
but banners
are kind of my...
Oh.
Holy Makes-No-
Sense-Whatsoever.
PIERCE: Whole thing
took 25 minutes tops.
ALL: Huh.
Early weekend?
Guys, I need to apologize
for my behavior today.
When I switched bodies
with Jeffrey...
Nope.
I thought I knew
what it would be like
to have Jeffrey
inside of me...
That did not happen.
...but as it turns out,
having Jeffrey
inside of me...
Nope again.
...only brought out
the worst in me.
Which is to say,
having Jeffrey
inside of me...
No one was
inside of anyone!
...was wrong...
...to have Jeffrey
inside of me.
Shut up!
So I'm sorry.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I scolded Leonard today,
and according
to Greendale bylaws,
I now have to grant him
three wishes.
Um, we need to get scolded
by the dean immediately.
SHIRLEY: Mmm-hmm.
Oh, man. Football is "frun."
That is an interest I have.
Also, plumbing
and air conditioning
are things I think about.
(LAUGHS)
Come on, man.
What are we...
What's happening?
I couldn't...
I'm sorry, keep rolling.
Okay. Come on.
Feetball is...
(LAUGHS)
"Feetball"?
"Feetball"!
Did I say...
Dorks!
Stop doing outtakes.
You switched bodies
last week.
Hey, guys,
I just want to apologize...
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my God!
Hey, Dean, walk much?
Am I right? (LAUGHING)
I'm sorry, I never do this.
Dean, we stopped
doing outtakes.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, we did that.
Oh, no worries.
Thanks for including me. Okay.
Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
No? Still not doing it?
Okay.