Hmm.
Shirley, did you ever date
Roger Ebert?
Excuse me?
Nothing.
Britta, did you ever
take pictures of your feet
and post them
on the internet
for money?
Sha-ha! No.
Guys, this history final
is going to be killer.
We have to study.
(SIGHS)
It's no fair
Professor Cornwallis
turned all
hard-assed again.
Lucky Pierce.
Donating his
kidney to Gilbert
to get out of it.
I never thought
he'd be that generous.
Although,
he did seem disappointed
that the operation
didn't involve
sleeping with
a Russian woman,
then waking up
in a bathtub
full of ice.
Hmm.
JEFF: Guys!
Hmm?
History!
I am studying history.
I'm studying our history.
ALL: Abed!
JEFF: Nobody bite.
We agreed no biting.
But, Jeff,
it's a graduation gift.
You see, on the surface
we seem like
just a group of people
from diverse backgrounds who
have become unlikely friends.
But according
to my research,
our paths have crossed
many times.
We were destined to meet.
Like a team of superheroes.
This is our origin story.
And here...we...go.
Abed, we don't have
origin stories.
We have lives.
Well, at least...
Yep, just me.
So you're saying
we're all connected
like the classic
French film trilogy
Bleu, Blanc, Rouge?
No, like something
more accessible.
Like  Unbreakable.
Wow.
Abed, I know
it's disappointing to you,
but we're not superheroes.
This is the real world,
not some
comic book adventure.
I've done it.
I've infiltrated the school.
I've learned its secrets.
I've gained everyone's trust.
And now, on the anniversary
of my empire's destruction,
vengeance will be mine.
(DISTORTED VOICE)
No, vengeance will be ours.
Okay, can you stop that?
It really creeps me out.
(NORMAL VOICE) I'm sorry.
Just really love this thing.
(DISTORTED VOICE)
Skymall.
(EVIL LAUGHTER)
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
I've been doing exhaustive
research into our lives.
Once I find the last
one or two missing pieces,
I'll have conclusive proof
that we were all
destined to meet.
This is how
we're all connected.
I call it the crazy quilt
of destiny
mainly because
the loom of fate
was already taken.
Really?
Look.
I don't care what tricks
or nonsense you have
in your scrapbook,
Martha Stewart,
but there's no way
you're gonna
get me to believe
there's some outside force
controlling my destiny.
And I think you used
that particular phrasing
because I know
you've seen  Star Wars.
(GASPS)
Everybody's seen  Star Wars.
Yes, but you first saw it
when it was
re-released in 1982
at the Greendale palladium
at 4:15 in the afternoon.
And it was the best time
you ever had with your father.
How did you know that?
You keep this ticket stub
in your wallet.
Abed, you can't...
Give it back!
Whoa!
Our story begins
in the distant mists
of a lost era:
(ECHOING) 2008.
I know you're
all wondering
how I do it.
How do I balance
straight As,
extracurriculars,
and Israeli folk dancing
every Friday night?
It's a simple matter
of organization,
dedication, and...
And we're back!
Then I drink your milkshake.
(LAUGHTER)
Ah, that will never get old.
You guys gotta see my  Juno.
Hey, Troy.
So I heard you
weren't doing that
great in algebra,
and you know,
if you need
a tutor for math,
I'd be happy to help.
I'm being
recruited by colleges
to play football.
Oh.
I don't have time for math.
The only thing
that matters to me
are statistics.
Ooh!
Uh, that's also
a type of math.
(BELL RINGS)
But we already knew
I went to high school
with Troy,
and it's not like he even
remembered I existed.
Yeah, I don't
remember her at all.
We should probably
drop this.
BRITTA: Wait,
where's Pierce on this chart?
His contribution
to the group has
already been noted.
Pierce Hawthorne.
Fixture at Greendale.
Unavoidable.
Hey, is that a sad face?
I wouldn't know.
You have to look deeper.
Here. Take this, for example.
It's a receipt I found
in the back of Shirley's
sock drawer on Thanksgiving.
You went in my bedroom
for some comic book thing?
Oh, no, my feet were cold.
Ah, here.
You should probably
wash those.
Oh.
ABED: Discovering the receipt
was dumb luck,
but it proves
that we were at the mall
on the exact same day.
Shirley, do remember
what you bought for $54
at the Love Hut?
What? Hmm? No.
So excited about tonight,
honey.
Uh-huh. It's been too long
since we had adult time
without the kids.
(LAUGHS) Oh!
Well, I may have
an anniversary
surprise for you too.
Well, I'm in public,
but, uh...
You know you gonna get it,
right?
You gonna get it!
(GIGGLING)
So we were at the mall
on the same day.
Unbreakable.
Mail call.
That's all right.
Won't be needing it today.
But Kevin always
takes the mail.
Well, today's mail's
kind of important.
It's the day that I send in
Greendale's lease renewal.
Lease re-new-al?
It's a critical document.
See, Greendale
sublets our land from
the Arapaho nation.
Ah.
Miss a renewal
and faster than you can say
"wounded knee,"
we turn into a casino
and midsize concert venue.
So you only trust me
with busywork?
Oh, no, that's not...
Kevin, ah... (LAUGHS)
I cannot resist
those puppy dog eyes.
Here.
Ah! Now, I have time
to hit the seamstress.
(GIGGLING)
Guess all I have to say
is "Ladies and gentlemen,
"Greendale resort and casino
presents Steve Winwood."
Okay, I just need to find
the one last smoking gun,
and I think
this might be it.
I found it in a copy of
The Greendale
Communist Worker.
Look familiar?
Oh, my God.
This is me and my anarchist
collective at the courthouse.
We called ourselves
the An-her-chists.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
Did you guys know
that Jeff's in that photo?
BOTH: What!
Jeff. My man.
Congrats on getting
your case thrown out.
Your argument
was a masterpiece.
I mean,
it was definitely creative.
Creative?
He convinced a judge
to forgive
five years back taxes
by getting him to agree
that you humping
an American flag
to  Back in Black
was not stripping
but actually not-for-profit
performance art.
Ch-chk...boom!
Blew me away.
BRITTA: Come on, let's go!
Thank you.
Thank you for defending
a woman's right
to use her body
however she chooses.
I can honestly say that right
is very important to me.
Aw!
REPORTER:
Excuse me, Mr. Winger,
can we get a...
You're a hero.
Hi.
Guys! We have
got to capitalize
on this momentum.
It is time An-her-chists
finally takes a stand
on animals rights.
There is a medical lab
in an office building nearby.
Next week,
I say we break in there...
Actually, we were thinking
this is our last hurrah.
But this was
our first hurrah.
We're just getting going.
Britta, we're done.
I had a hamburger
the other day,
and suddenly
I'm not cold
all the time.
Fine. Go.
I don't need you.
What's an anarchist to do
without her organization?
Jeffrey, how could you?
Well, I was
a really good lawyer.
Mysti is the stripper
that Andre cheated
on me with,
and you defended her.
Shirley, I...
If you hadn't gotten
that homewrecker off,
Andre never
would've met her.
ABED: Jeff ends
Shirley's marriage.
See? I told you
we were always
destined to meet.
Hmm.
ABED: I knew Shirley and Jeff
went to the same rec center,
but I had no idea
their paths crossed again.
This is good.
This is really great.
We're really filling in
some plot holes here.
This is good stuff.
It's really good.
Have I missed something?
These aren't plot holes, Abed.
This is my life.
But this kinda connection
only makes our origin story
more compelling.
Like how awesome it is
when Uncle Ben is murdered
in  Spider-Man.
Hmm.
My marriage almost ended.
If it weren't for Jeff,
that jezebel
would've been in jail
instead of between
my Laura Ashley sheets.
Hey, this is not my fault.
And by the way,
the case didn't work out
too great for me either.
It was supposed to make
my career,
but it put a target
on my back.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Michael Phelps, really?
And it doesn't affect
his breathing?
Nope.
Mysti, can I talk to Jeff
for a moment?
I will go, uh,
powder my nose.
For real.
Listen.
There's this rumor
going around the firm
that you never received
an undergraduate degree.
(LAUGHS)
That's ridiculous.
I know.
I mean, some jag
is obviously jealous
of your rising star.
But the fact is,
until this is settled,
the bar isn't gonna
let you practice.
SHIRLEY:
So you got caught
in your own lie?
I almost lost my family.
How does your
little tragedy
even compare?
Because I had to go
to school here.
Abed, do not write that down.
It's not like
I made Andre cheat.
Well, I happen to think
it's cool that
we're all connected,
even if some of it's
in bad ways.
I mean,
I'm finally willing
to forgive Annie
for ruining high school.
Wait, I ruined your time
in high school?
Yeah, you did.
You guys doing keg stands?
Yeah!
Anyone can do
a keg stand.
I'm gonna do a keg flip.
Hey, everybody,
look at this.
(ALL CHANTING "TROY")
Ah!
Oh!
Oh, my football knee!
Why!
Can I have some corn nuts?
Wah! No! No!
ANNIE: That had
nothing to do with me.
And you already admitted
that you faked that injury
because you couldn't
take the pressure
of those football recruiters.
I faked my injury
because of what
you said to me.
Because of what I said?
You didn't even
remember that I went
to school with you.
I may have lied
about that too.
GIRL:
Hey, guys, it's time to do
senior class superlatives!
(CHEERS)
Okay, the first award
is "most handsome."
And the winner is...
Troy Barnes.
Of course it is.
"Most popular."
Troy Barnes.
No! You guys are awesome.
"Best smile."
(MIMICS BRUSHING)
Ha ha, gotta keep 'em white.
"Best moves."
"Best practical joker."
"Coolest locker."
And now, the last award
of the night.
"Most likely to succeed."
Okay, this has to go to me,
because I am most likely
to succeed.
It's just a fact.
You guys know.
And the winner is...
Troy Barnes.
(CHEERS)
(SCREAMS)
You have got
to be kidding me!
Troy Barnes,
most likely to succeed?
I'm the damn valedictorian
and head of student council
and president of
Campus Crusade for Christ.
And I'm Jewish!
And you are just
some mindless robot.
You just go wherever
they tell you to run.
I'm sorry.
Do you go to my school?
(LAUGHTER)
Oh!
(SCREAMING)
(ALL REACTING)
Pop! Pop!
Your words cut me
more than hundreds
of non-tempered
glass shards could.
I had six different
reconstructive surgeries.
I went through withdrawal.
I had to smile
when I didn't
feel like smiling.
That hurts my face.
SHIRLEY:
Can we all just stop
dredging up the past?
The only thing
your fate web thing does
is point out how fragile
our happiness is.
If only Jeff hadn't
defended that woman,
if only Andre hadn't met her
after I left the restaurant,
if only I didn't
have to pick up
my kids at the mall, I...
Wait.
When? Which mall?
Oh, my God.
Hey, what movie
you guys gonna see?
The Phantom Menace.
It's kind of old.
(SIGHS) And why
do you wanna see it?
Because we like  Star Wars.
Okay, if you like  Star Wars,
why do you wanna murder it
and urinate on its grave?
The prequels are terrible.
I mean, seriously,
wouldn't Chewbacca,
at some point, go,
"Hey, Yoda, I know that guy"?
He has double light sabers.
That's stupid.
You're both stupid.
Well, why are you here
to see the movie?
I'm not.
I go wherever it plays
to warn people.
You've been warned.
Stranger said what to him?
Okay, fine.
I'll come get you.
I'm sorry, baby,
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
Okay, just stand there, okay?
This can't be.
I don't see why
I have to go
to a therapist.
Because after that
woman chewed them
out for three hours,
the theater got
a restraining order
against you.
Yalla.
ABED: Hey, Doc.
By the way,
someone just stole
your prescription pad.
I'm trying to liberate you!
(MONKEY SQUEALING)
Ow!
You're the crazy man
at the mall!
You're the one who got me
busted for drugs!
You were
out there somewhere
and you weren't
looking for me?
JEFF: In fairness, Annie,
running through a glass door
might've been
the drug tip-off.
All this time,
I wondered what it was
that brought our group
together.
But I forgot one thing
all heroes need.
They need an enemy.
Batman has the Joker,
the Justice League
has The Legion of Doom,
and this study group...
Has me.
I'm the supervillain.
Why didn't I see it before?
I'm emotionless, logical,
smarter than everybody else.
Hey!
I tried sawing off
Jeff's arm.
Why do you keep
saying that?
I should go. It's not
safe to be around me.
I'm just as bad.
I couldn't handle the monkey,
so I traded it in
for a glaucoma brownie,
even though I knew
if it bit someone,
it would make them
a teensy bit psychotic.
Britta's right.
We've all made
some bad decisions.
And if you really wanna know
who the villain is here,
it's me.
Ah.
Wee! (GIGGLES)
Yeesh, I didn't think
it was possible
to put more glitter on.
It's coming off of you
like pig-pen.
Well, some people
seem to like it.
This married guy
just gave me
his phone number.
Can you believe
his wife left him
on their anniversary?
You gonna call him?
I mean, he did just win
a bunch of money.
I don't know though.
You don't know what?
You're not married.
You gotta grab
what you want
in this life.
That's the way it works.
Someone just took something
important from me.
And you know what?
I admire him for it.
All right, I mean,
I guess I'll go talk to him.
You do that.
And I'm gonna go get
"crap on other
people's lawns" Drunk.
To a memorable evening
for both of us.
Maybe you coincidentally
affected some of us.
But I actively
endorsed pain.
I was the bad guy,
and...
I'd like to think
I'm not that guy anymore.
Also, and I hate
to bring this up,
you did once make me
pee myself.
Well, I guess
we're even then.
I might finish
studying at home.
Just ten minutes ago,
I would've been so excited
about that peeing thing.
I wanted to make a prequel,
and I ruined everything.
I guess it could happen
to anyone.
I should probably
write George Lucas
a note of apology.
Okay, let's not get crazy.
And you didn't
ruin anything.
SHIRLEY: May I sit here?
JEFF: Shirley,
what are you doing here?
Oh, just wanted
some yogurt.
And I do know
you're not that
person anymore.
Are you sure?
'Cause I was
awfully good at it.
Well, we all do bad things
every now and again.
I mean, I put
a stripper's head
through a jukebox.
Hmm.
What are you guys
doing here?
I guess we all
really wanted yogurt.
You know what's weird?
This is where I first decided
to go to Greendale.
ANNIE: Wait, really?
This is where I was
when I first decided
to go to Greendale.
You're kidding me.
Senor Chang, I know you're
as disappointed as I am
in the caliber of students
we have at Greendale.
But the mall offers
a whole new
valuable demographic
of people awake
during the daytime.
All right,
I'll pass flyers
at yogurtsburgh.
Self-serve yogurt.
Those doofuses already know
one marketable skill.
Okay, Ben...
But it still has
the tags on!
So I lost the receipt.
It's not like I even got
to wear it,
because my husband's
a tasteless man slut.
What...
Hey, littering!
(GASPING)
This better not awaken
anything in me.
God, this day...
I thought pushing
that woman's head
through a jukebox
would make me feel better,
but I'm just...
Out of $54...
And a marriage.
Crystal Skull was aliens,
so it's a pretty great film.
You guys seen this?
Guys, working the program
with you has been so great.
I feel like I'm finally ready
to get my life back on track.
Last chance.
Just walk over
there right now
and apologize
to the theater manager.
Midichlorians.
Midichlorians!
Fine.
Then you're not going
to film school!
Hi! Do you have
any vegan froyo?
Do you even know
what froyo is?
Fine. Do you have
a job application?
Hey.
That weird guy
hasn't blinked once.
Oh, yeah.
What a dweeb.
Yeah, what a dweeb.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, nice shot, man!
Hey, do you work
at Greendale?
Work? That's putting it
charitably.
Greendale Community College
is a total joke.
They'd give a degree
to a monkey.
Hey, does Ian Duncan
still teach psychology
at Greendale?
That drunken limey?
That's the one.
He's got tenure.
Maybe getting my degree
won't be as hard as I thought.
(PIERCE GRUNTING)
WOMAN:
Sir, what are you doing?
WOMAN: Can we get
some help out here?
Some old guy
broke the machine and is
faking a heart attack.
Oh, wait.
Ah, stupid.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Cool, cool, cool.
Wait, so was that old guy
really Pierce?
We'll never know,
because he'll never
ever remember.
What are the chances
of all of us
ending up at the same place
at the same time twice?
Abed, it's amazing.
I mean, yes,
2008 was the height
of the slightly sour
frozen yogurt craze, but...
That still doesn't explain it.
Maybe we really were
all meant to be together.
I'm not sure I understand it,
but maybe we don't have to.
What I do know is that
the ways our paths crossed,
even when they were bad,
all led us to this point.
And I wouldn't have it
any other way.
So what you're saying
is that we're all each other's
uncle Ben's murder.
And we're all Spider-Men.
Yeah.
Let's say I'm saying that.
Mmm, I think we know
whose will this really is.
Yeah, I think I do.
I'll be right back.
Hello?
Hey, Abed.
(SIGHS) Just doing
some pilates.
I was looking for you.
Wha... I...
We discovered
you're the reason
we all went to Greendale.
You linked
all of our stories.
Like how the cosmic cube
assembled The Avengers.
That, and the 4-billion-dollar
deal with Disney.
Turns out
you were always one of us.
So I came to see
if you wanted to get
some frozen yogurt.
Really?
That's...
That's all I ever wanted.
But it's too late.
Here's another thing
I realized.
Because of you
we got to reinvent
ourselves at Greendale.
Everyone should have
the same chance,
don't you think...
Chang?
It's not Chang.
It's Kevin.
How long have you known?
Known what?
Only you know
who you really are.
Also, you may have
experimental monkey fever.
You coming?
Yeah.
Actually, can we stop
at the post office first?
I have something to mail
for the dean.
It's confidential
and I don't wanna
talk about it,
so stop interrogating me.
I'm out.
I Chang'd my mind.
(DISTORTED VOICE)
You're too in to be out.
Hey!
Hi!
You want some refills?
On me, huh?
Refills?
You want some?
Time for plan "B".
(EVIL LAUGHTER)
(DISTORTED LAUGHTER)