Hey.
Get out of my chair,
or I'll have you disbarred.
Oh, wait.
That already happened.
Cash.
Tango.
My old partner
in my new firm.
(LAUGHS)
Does it get any better?
Not unless you leave.
(CHUCKLES)
Still got it.
So a little birdie told me
you're graduating
kiddie college.
You must be excited
to get that lollipop.
Hey.
It's a sticker.
Ha.
I know you're busy, not,
so allow me to whip it out.
Come work with me.
You'll be a full partner,
six figures,
corner office,
three secretaries.
What's that?
Not enough money?
I'll double it.
Bam, done.
That's how we negotiate.
Lunch?
Wow.
I drive a hard bargain.
But, Mark,
aren't you worried
I'm a little out of practice?
The only cases
I've tried lately are
about sandwiches and yams.
Please, you were
a better lawyer
when you weren't a lawyer
than most lawyers I know.
It's still in you.
I'll give it some thought.
Just shake
my hand, idiot.
It's simple.
I like simple.
Take a look around, Winger.
This is your new old life.
I don't get it.
We just had Christmas,
and now it's warm outside.
Of course it is, dummy.
We just finished
fall-spring semester.
Bring on summer-winter.
I can't wait.
My final film school class
is just called Opinions.
Professor Taylor
is scheduled to teach,
but I have a rebuttal.
Lucky. I transferred
to Forensics late and
got the worst classes.
Skull fragment collection,
advanced advanced decomp,
and intro to senselessness
were all full.
I still have a year
of A/C repair left.
I passed all my classes,
so now I just do yoga
while the teachers
write down my wisdoms.
Wait a minute.
Jeff passed History.
He's graduating early.
I'm totally unprepared
to deal with this.
No, Annie,
please, don't...
(NOISEMAKERS BLOWING)
Well, it's official.
It's on a banner.
Congratulations, Jeffrey.
You worked hard
not to work hard
to earn that degree.
Yeah, you took
so many blow-off classes
and pointless electives.
What did you end up
majoring in?
Education.
PIERCE: You had to win,
didn't you?
When I was inches
from the finish line.
Pierce, you have
so many credits,
they have grand-credits.
Just graduate already.
When's the
graduation ceremony?
Never.
It's community college.
You just send in some papers
and they stop charging you.
It's moving,
in its own way.
So this is it?
A banner and some soda
Troy forgot to bring?
No.
As far as graduations go,
it's boring but grounded.
I was hoping for more.
Can we at least
walk with you to
the dean's office?
What, now? No.
I was just...
I was going to
mail it in next week,
or, you know,
whenever.
Don't be silly.
We started as
a study group,
we'll finish
as a study group.
All for one, and one dude
we can all leave behind.
Everybody,
go quickly.
Go.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
Hey.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
All right, Mr. Winger.
Et al. Britta.
Emotions are
running high,
so I will keep this
tight and short.
You always do.
I see you have
all the necessary paperwork.
Necessary?
You asked for
proof of inseam.
Ah, Jeffrey.
I'm going to miss our playful,
"Get a room already" banter.
Oh, dean.
I can come back.
No, I can do this.
Just need to sign
the old John dean-cock
and you will
be graduated.
So this is it?
Mmm-hmm.
Huh.
I, uh... I expected
a little more pageantry.
I'm listening.
Annie's right.
We should throw a party
to mark the occasion.
(SQUEALS)
A small one.
The teensiest.
Just close friends,
a small cake...
Maybe some flowers,
an archway...
A string quartet.
Ooh, he could
wear a suit.
Starting to sound
like a wedding.
Not a wedding.
Just your average,
low-key diploma signing,
to which you're all
cordially invited,
tomorrow afternoon.
Tomorrow?
Is that enough time
to plan a whole wedding?
Absolutely.
I'll get my book.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Listen, I can't
do a big party.
It's too much.
Oh, I see
what's going on here.
This is about you getting
cold feet about graduating.
Pshh, yeah.
I've been looking
forward to graduation
since freshman registration.
I already got
a job lined up
at my old partner's firm.
Well, then,
let them eat cake.
It's just,
I'm worried that the
group might not be able
to handle it,
you know, emotionally.
Everyone wants you
to graduate, Jeff.
Well,
what about Abed?
I mean,
the stress of me leaving
might send him spiraling.
Come on,
give him some more credit.
He's really progressed
since he opened up
to my therapizing.
Do you remember last year,
when he wouldn't stop
talking about that
Darkest Timeline thing?
The one
where I lost my arm?
And Pierce died,
and Annie went insane,
and he blamed it all
on you throwing some dice.
He has not brought
that up in months.
You're right, Britta.
I just need
to give Abed a chance.
Then it's settled.
The six of us will take
Astronomy next semester.
So now
you're leaving me out.
No,
we're leaving Jeff out.
So I'm not even the one
who gets left out anymore.
Everything's Jeff, Jeff...
Jeff.
This seat taken?
(ALL LAUGHING)
So everyone still excited
about the big shindig?
ABED: Totally.
I was worried about
the wedding-graduation
mash up,
but it's testing
really well with women.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
Oh, well,
that's a load off.
Hey, we should
probably figure out
who's bringing
the soda now, right?
Just so there's not
another hang up.
I brought it.
I just drank it all.
It's okay.
I've got it covered.
No, no, no.
You've already
done so much.
Besides, I think I have
a fun and fair way
to decide
which of the six of us
will bring the soda.
We'll roll for it.
It didn't land
on a number.
That probably means nothing.
Or it means everything.
Let's hope not.
You know what,
I'll bring the soda.
Don't worry,
I'll make sure there
aren't any more hang-ups.
Must I bear
this cross forever?
I was hoping
for more.
(SINGING TO THE TUNE OF
POMP AND CIRCUMSTANCE)
♪ Dean, dean, dean, dean,
dean, dean
♪ Dean, dean, dean,
dean, dean, dean
dean, dean ♪
(SINGING TO THE TUNE OF
BRIDAL CHORUS)
♪ Dean, dean, dean, dean
♪ Dean, dean, dean, dean,
dean, dean, dean ♪
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(GLASS BREAKING)
Catherine?
Do not even tell me
you dropped that cake.
Parasites.
Hey.
What's going on?
Why are you trying
to avoid graduating?
I wish I knew.
I think it's because
you're scared
to take this law job
with your old partner.
But don't let that
stop you from graduating.
Take the job,
don't take the job.
Either way, your friends
are always going
to be here
to support you.
Good to know.
See you at graduation.
And they call us
the worst.
Took you long enough.
Hey, nobody said
you had to travel naked.
Oh. You brought the good one.
You hold that,
I'll do the sleeve.
Wait for the click.
There...
Ah. Good.
Middle finger
works great now.
It's worse
than I thought.
They made lame Jeff
too lame to leave Greendale.
He's got to take that job.
But how do we
make him do that?
By turning the
study group against him
so he'll run screaming
from this rancid cocoon
into the welcoming arms
of darkness.
How hard is that
to understand?
It's not.
I just like
when you talk down
to me like a child.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH MOANING)
Oh! Jeff.
It's bad luck
to see the graduation
before the graduation.
I had to talk to you.
Today is bringing up
so many emotions.
It's a lot
to take in.
I'm not making you
feel nervous
about graduating,
am I?
Well, you are making me
feel something.
And it's not
about graduating.
I'm saying
I'm hot for you.
Me?
Is this for real?
Is my beating heart
for real?
Oh, Annie.
I don't know if it's
the beautiful decorations,
or the impending
floral archway,
but there's
something about this
that feels so right.
It's the perfect moment
to remember you by.
Remember me by?
I'm not going anywhere.
Exactly.
You're going nowhere.
I'm about to
return to my cool,
adult, lawyer life,
and you're going
to be stuck here,
playing high school.
Why are you saying this?
So you face the facts.
Once I graduate,
I'm gone.
Winger,
streaking on your
last day of school?
Respect.
Oh, so I got
the save the date
for your graduation.
Should I bring a date,
or try to hook up there?
I'm not going to your
stupid graduation, jerk.
I can't believe you said
those things to me.
What things?
Don't play dumb.
You want to leave? Leave.
See if I care.
What did you do?
I have no earthly idea.
Hook up there.
Hello, Abed.
Hello, Evil Jeff.
What?
How did you...
I may not be good
with facial expressions,
but I know
an evil doppelganger
when I see one.
Plus your arm makes a noise
every time you move it.
Silence.
(MECHANICAL ARM WHIRRING)
Are you here
to kill Jeff?
Oh, you non-evils
are so naive.
I'm here to save Jeff
from the smothering teat
of his study group.
Is that a paintball gun?
You wish.
Cool.
Wait. Cold.
(GROANS)
How did I get
to the dean's office?
Hi.
Out of my chair, monkey.
The Darkest Timeline.
Annie.
(SOBS)
Um, okay,
let's start with "huh?"
Jeff, I'm sorry.
I made it all up.
I've been so upset
about you graduating
that I've gone
a little crazy, emotionally.
Oh, good.
I thought I was
losing my mind.
Make it up to you
with a hug?
This breakfast sandwich cart
is such a great idea.
It's never
too early for Shirley...
To make a boatload off
of hung over college kids.
Speaking of
great idea having,
hear me out.
It's called
"the Troy-jan horse."
It goes bread,
lettuce, ham, ham,
bacon, chocolate...
Oh, how you doing,
the graduate?
Just stopping by
to hand out some un-vites
to my graduation.
Here's one for
the desperate housewife
who spends more time
with her pathetic business
than with her family.
And you.
If you call a sandwich
a "Troy-jan horse,"
people are
going to think
there's horse in it.
Oh, my dreams.
Whatever, losers.
See you never.
Where's Abed?
Is anyone here?
Hello, Abed.
Welcome to our home.
Hello, Evil Abed.
It's just Abed now.
After we met,
I abandoned my evil goal
to focus on brightening
my own timeline instead.
Do you live here alone?
Yes.
Evil Troy moved out
when I gave up the cause.
Now he only listens
to Evil Jeff,
who sort of took over
this year, villain-wise.
Jeff left Greendale
and became a scummy
lawyer again,
but the more evil
he got,
the more he became
tortured by the idea
that there's still
a good Jeff out there,
being good somewhere.
That's why he forced me
to show him
how to travel
between timelines.
My God.
This is so cool.
I know.
You have no idea
how long I've been waiting
to talk to you about it.
Kind of a  Superman III
meets that  Star Trek episode
meets season three
of  The Cape.
The Cape was cancelled.
Not here.
They retooled it for cable,
and it's awesome.
Want to see it?
Desperately.
But I need to get
back to my timeline
and stop Evil Jeff.
So I came to the only person
who could help me. Me.
I'll get you home, Abed.
But first,
you'll need some supplies.
Everyone must be
running late.
Here, Jeffrey.
You're graduated.
Take your precious diploma
and just go.
I cannot believe
the hurtful things
you said to me
in my office.
I'll have you know
that wanting
a little pageantry
in your life
isn't a crime
or a lifestyle choice.
Okay, Annie,
something definitely
weird is happening.
No one's here,
the dean is mad at me,
and he is never
mad at me, and...
A third reason.
Congratulations, Jeff.
Don't worry
about the study group.
You can talk
to them later.
Why don't you and I
go celebrate
someplace private
and boozy?
Annie, why are you
acting like a mistress
in a lifetime movie?
(LAUGHS)
You're funny.
Oh, sweetheart,
you dropped
your phone earlier.
You've got a voicemail
from a guy named Mark?
You should call him.
Not now.
I have to find the others
and figure this out.
Crap.
We're losing him.
What?
BOTH: Who are you?
You're me?
But how?
Enough of the pleasantries.
I've come
from the Darkest Timeline
to make sure
you take that job.
It's essential
to our future.
You want it, idiot,
so take it.
I can't. I've spent
almost four years here,
growing and changing
and making dioramas.
I'm not that
guy anymore.
You're wrong.
Greendale may have dulled
your killer instinct,
but trust me,
it's still in you.
It's time to leave this place
and reclaim your proper life.
No. Not without
my study group.
Ugh. Now who's
in a lifetime movie?
Then I'll be rid of you
another way.
Friendship!
Mmm. Cold.
Well,
the subtle approach failed.
What's next?
Explain it slowly.
Need some help?
Let's burn this mother down.
Jeff must be
graduating about now.
I wonder
if anyone's there.
Doubt he cares.
Pierce won't even
respond to my texts.
I wonder what terrible things
Jeff said about him.
I've got some guesses.
(ALL GASPING)
Let me finish.
Look, I know
this may sound crazy,
and more
than a little convenient,
but whatever I said to you,
it wasn't me.
It was Evil Jeff.
(SCOFFS) Come on.
Something happened
when I rolled that die.
Something terrible.
Something only nerds
can understand.
Mmm-hmm.
You have to believe me.
They're coming for us.
No.
We're coming for them.
Abed,
where have you been?
The Darkest Timeline.
You guys never believe me,
so this time,
I brought proof,
the doppeldeaner.
(ALL GASPING)
Abed brought me here
to prove to all of you...
Whoa.
Actually, I figured that
these paintball warping guns
would convince you.
Listen up, people.
We've got an inter-dimensional
battle on our hands.
Our evil counterparts
are waging a war,
and it's either us or us.
All right.
Let's light up
these dark suckers.
Okay, everyone.
Stay sharp.
If you see yourself,
warp on sight.
I'd like to warp myself
to a dairy-free mudslide.
That's just vodka, Shirley.
I know what it is.
MAN: Ah-ha.
Pierce? We thought
you were dead.
Hell, no.
After I got shot,
I faked my death
to teach
you all a lesson.
Lesson about what?
Who can remember?
It was more than a year ago.
And yet,
here you all are,
planning an invasion
without me.
Again,
we thought you were dead.
Listen, I can help you guys
beat the lame study group.
Just tell me
how this works.
Fine.
It's complicated,
but basically,
the first person
to shoot themselves wins.
(PAINTBALL GUNSHOT)
Winner.
Well, that bow
tied itself.
Dang, I got hair dye
on my coat.
Dang, it's spreading.
Damn it, Britta.
Did you shoot yourself too?
Every time.
Hey.
Don't talk to her
like that.
Every time.
We're here. Scatter.
Get help.
Can't hide forever,
lame Annie.
Just let me shoot you.
You'll love
the Darkest Timeline.
We're sleeping
with Jeff there.
What? We are?
All the time.
And he loves it.
(GRUNTS)
Nobody sleeps with Jeff.
Not even me.
I've been
counting bullets.
One of us is out.
Is it you?
Yes.
Why would you
tell me that?
To sound intimidating.
Oh. Almost worked.
Ballin'.
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Okay.
Only Evil Jeff is left.
You've got
to take him out.
Why don't I just give him
what he wants?
What?
You can't give up now.
Why not?
Because it's not real.
Look around, Jeff.
Haven't you noticed
the vending machines
are full of meats
and hard-boiled eggs?
Or that
all the background students
are attractive women?
Hi.
Yeah.
This is a world you've
created in your own mind.
The real battle
is within.
You're afraid to graduate
because you think
Greendale has
changed you too much.
So part of you
wants Evil Jeff to win,
because then you could
go backwards and pretend
you're the same guy
you were four years ago.
But you're not.
You're stronger.
You're better.
You have friends.
No, screw that.
You have a family.
Wait.
If this is all
in my mind,
then I don't really
need to fight him.
Don't logic this one
away from me.
We finally figured out a way
to make paintball cool again.
Hey, handsome.
(YELLING)
On second thought,
who needs to roll a die?
And who cares
if we have soda?
As long as you guys
are with me,
I have everything
I need to graduate.
Yeah. Forget soda.
Friends, Greendalians,
human beings,
we are gathered
here today to honor
that sacred and
eternal bond between
a student and his dean.
Neither time nor distance
nor screening one's calls
could ever sever what
nature herself has ordained.
When two men are drawn...
I'll take it
from here, Craig.
Fair enough.
I was reaching.
Three and a half years ago,
when I came to Greendale,
I met six
very important people.
Ooh. Burn on Britta.
Sorry, seven.
And meeting these people
changed my life.
Yep.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what to say.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah, okay.
Whatever.
I'm so used
to being the guy
who can talk his way
out of anything,
but what do you say
when you don't
want a way out?
What you all have done
for me is indescribable.
It's unbelievable.
And my love for you
is immeasurable,
even when you
split it seven ways.
Well said, Jeffrey.
If anyone here
should have just cause
why Jeffrey Tobias Winger
should not be graduated,
speak now
or forever...
(KNOCKING ON WINDOW)
Pierce.
You don't have to do this.
I'm ready to graduate.
Yeah?
Well, I'm ready
to graduate first.
Seems oddly appropriate.
Congratulations, Pierce.
(APPLAUSE)
Perfect.
So what's next
for Jeffrey Winger?
I'm thinking I might look
into some small local firms.
I'm going to
use my big mouth
to help the little guy.
BOTH: Aww.
Plus,
if I stay in town,
I can pop by
any time I want.
You know, just to settle
any group arguments
about who
misses me the most.
Oh...
What do you think?
To Jeff.
To Jeffrey.
BOTH:  ♪ Troy and Abed
in the morning ♪
Welcome back.
We've got a jam-packed show,
so let's get started.
Today, as always,
we'll be visited
once again
by Greendale's king
and supreme lord master,
Dean Chang.
Looks like
he'll be talking
about squash this time.
Oh, I'm super excited
for that.
And not only
because it's mandatory.
But first,
we'll take a spin
around the Timeline map
and find out what's
happening in the universes
that parallel ours.
Thanks, us.
I'm standing here
in Timeline five,
where things
are pretty much normal.
Normal?
Troy, people are
on fire in Nairobi.
You call that normal?
I've become much more
conscious of world issues
since Troy and I
decided to give our
baby an African name.
Isn't that right, Chewbacca?
It means,
"He who hunts bounties."
Back to you.
Wow, it sounds like
things are really
heating up in Nairobi.
That's nothing
compared to the fire
in our studio audience.
Hey, idiots.
How many times
have I told you,
the show doesn't
really exist.
No one's watching.
Duh-doy. We know.
Yeah, we're just
messing around.
See you at lunch,
Evil Jeff.
See you at lunch.
BOTH:  ♪ Troy and Abed
in the morning ♪