I am the system.
I consume humanity.
There is no escape.
JEFF: Objection!
♪ Jeff Winger,
hero at law
♪ Best lawyer you ever saw
♪ Hero to freedom,
defender of liberty
♪ South of the forty
on Lincoln
♪ You park for free
♪ Jeff ♪
Are you a good person
being sued, oppressed,
or beaten?
I can help,
and that's
the Winger guarantee.
Call 555-her...
Maybe you should've
spent less money
on special effects.
Huh, thanks a lot,
Francis Ford Repo Man.
(MOROSE PIANO MUSIC)
Oh, Jeff Winger!
♪ Loser at law
♪ Rented office
in a mini mall ♪
Relax, Tango.
I come in peace.
Way I see it,
I screwed you.
I got screwed back.
Now we can bygone
the bygones,
because I got
a juicy new client
and a bone to throw you.
You hear about that bridge
that collapsed upstate?
A human could've said that
without salivating.
I represent Marvin Humphries,
the engineer who designed it.
He wants to seek damages.
From what?
His own pencil?
From the only school
reckless enough
to give him a degree
in engineering.
City-funded school,
deep government pockets.
Maybe you've heard of it.
Greendale Community College.
Weird choice, by the way,
the bachelor's degree
on the wall.
So you're gonna sue
my old school
and you're bothering
to tell me?
You have access there.
I need Marvin's
records to prove
that he was
irresponsibly educated.
Well, why don't you
just subpoena?
Right, so they can have
a shredding party.
See, that's the
difference between you
and Greendale, Alan.
They wouldn't
shred evidence.
It's a good place
for good people.
It's a diploma mill.
It turns idiots
into bridge-collapsers
and Jeff Winger
into an attorney
that thought
he could help people?
Jeff, I once saw you convince
an arson victim
that he liked
his house better burned.
(CHUCKLES)
God, look what that
school did to you.
It took
all your money.
It took four years
of your life.
And worst of all,
it took your Winger moves.
I still got
my Winger moves.
Prove it.
Get me Humphries' records.
Because the next bone
you get thrown
might be
through a dude's zipper
in the warehouse district,
and I can't guarantee you
it'll be from me.
Look, I might be
broke, desperate,
and nearly homeless,
but I still got one thing
deep down inside
that gives me power...
That was it.
That was all I had.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
PELTON:
Welcome back, human beings.
Dean Pelton here,
wishing you another
magic year at Greendale,
ranked America's number two
community college
by
greendalecommunitycollege.com.
Regarding the recent
tragedy surrounding
a certain collapsed bridge,
we will be observing
a moment of silence
on the quad
followed by four years
of silence to the press.
I told you you'd be back.
Shut up, Leonard.
I'm not here.
I'm just a figment
of your creeping dementia.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Hi.
How would I go about
getting records
for certain alumni?
Why would you think
a stranger
could just walk in here
and do that?
You're, uh, Rita.
Rhonda.
I've always regretted
not telling you
how much you remind me
of my aunt.
It's more disarming
than it sounds.
I have a very attractive aunt.
Rhonda, why are you
wearing Jeff Winger's...
(GASPS)
Jeffrey.
Are you, uh, looking
for your friends?
They don't go here anymore.
Maybe you're looking
for something
that was in front of you
the whole time, just a pitch.
RHONDA:
He's asking for records
for a certain alumni.
In the midst of all this
Marvin Humphries business,
I doubt
this is a coincidence.
You're here to save me,
aren't you?
Yes.
Oh.
I thought
I might contact alumni
to form a committee.
The Save Greendale Committee.
Working title.
Jeffrey, I'm gonna cry.
Please don't.
Request denied.
Mmm.
Rhonda will let you
in the records room.
It's actually
your old study room.
After you
and your friends left,
it was closed
for sentimental reasons.
And asbestos reasons,
but it's clean
as a whistle now.
(SIGHS)
"Harassment reports,"
"Hazardous waste citations,"
"Herpes comma
water fountains."
Come on.
Where's Humphries?
I see your value now.
Abed, why?
"I see your value now."
It's a callback
to when we met first season.
And me calling years
"seasons" is a callback
to my first season dialogue,
and me calling...
Abed, I know what
makes you off-putting,
but why are you here?
The dean called me about
the Save Greendale Committee.
Can I join?
Well, I...
Oh, no.
Who else did he call?
Just me.
I called everyone else.
(EXCITED SQUEALING
AND CHEERING)
Jeff!
(ALL SQUEALING)
Is that cool?
It's the coolest.
Jeff, if you wanted
to save Greendale,
why didn't you
call us first?
Well, you guys just got
sprung from this joint,
and I figured you had
careers to get started.
Yeah, working hard.
Ah, yes.
(ALL TALKING OVER EACH OTHER)
(CONVERSATION PETERS OUT)
What have they done
to our home?
The table's buried.
(BRITTA AND ANNIE WHINE)
(GRUNTING) I got it.
This is where
we became a family.
(CHUCKLES)
Jeff made us a family.
ANNIE: Hmm.
We could repilot it.
This could be like
Scrubs season nine,
a revamp, a do-over.
Jeff could come back
to Greendale as a teacher.
I'm not gonna be
a teacher, Abed.
That's lame.
Come on.
Sit in your chair.
Complete the table.
We want to help you
save Greendale.
ALL: Yeah!
Greendale! Greendale!
Greendale!
I got to go to the bathroom.
Mmm, give him space.
Repiloting can be intense.
New people show up.
Regulars shift roles
or even fall away.
Season nine of  Scrubs,
Zach Braff was only in
the first six episodes.
That son of a bitch.
After everything
Scrubs did for him?
I'm sorry.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Vision boarding.
Okay, vision boarding!
Oh, hi, Jeffrey.
Dean, I have to warn you
about something,
because it's the
right thing to do.
But first,
why is there a big
empty box on your desk
that says
"Humphries" on it?
Okay, the press has been
calling about Humphries,
and I didn't want any details
about his enrollment here
to be spun against us,
so now there are no details.
Oh, ooh.
That was his thesis.
Okay! So sue me!
This ain't Harvard, Jeffrey.
Okay, my job is
to give a certain number
of degrees per year,
or we could get shut down.
And that would be bad
because...
Ah, because then
I wouldn't have a job.
And, you know,
Greendale is a good place
for good people.
That whole spiel, huh?
Yeah.
That whole spiel.
(GRUMBLES)
(LINE RINGING)
Wingblade.
Shock me by impressing me.
He shredded Humphries.
What?
I told you!
How could you
let this happen?
Sir, I have to ask you
to leave the concierge desk.
(GROANS)
Jeff, this case
was all I had.
I am screwed!
My wife left.
My girlfriend dumped me.
And they're sisters, so now
the whole family's pissed.
Shut up.
Bring me all the paperwork
for filing a class action.
Letters of intent,
engagement, everything.
Multiple copies.
Winger, you just lost
our client!
Yeah.
But I can create
five new ones.
It's so dusty.
Let's get this
off the table.
And that's
the Winger guarantee.
Okay, maybe
we should brainstorm
fundraising ideas...
Oh!
That aren't bake sales...
Hey.
Or opening a zoo where
the humans are in cages
and the animals
come to visit.
G'oh!
(GROANS)
Are you okay, Jeff?
You left kind of freaked out.
Well...
I can't stop thinking
this school might be
in trouble
because of this
bridge-collapsing guy.
He's the one
making bad bridges.
That's like me
blaming owls for how much
I suck at analogies.
Sometimes a student
will claim, in court,
that their school
ruined their life,
and they'll win.
You want to save Greendale?
Make it litigation-proof.
How?
Think like the enemy.
How did Greendale
damage you, Annie?
It didn't. I love
hospital administration.
Is that your job?
Well...not yet.
But I administer things
to hospitals,
like these.
Pen?
"Futurza"?
They're a rising star
in pharmaceuticals.
They invented fibromyalgia
and the cure
for fibromyalgia.
You push drugs now?
That's ironic.
I push pens, Britta.
Speaking of irony,
how's the therapy market?
Depressed?
I'm on sabbatical.
You're Jewish?
I'm doing
hands-on research
about the psychology
of alcoholism.
You're a bartender,
aren't you?
Which is basically like
a modern-day therapist.
If somebody tells me
about a murder,
I can't tell anyone.
Wow, you're even bad
at bartending.
What about you?
Abed's working on
the next billion-dollar
social media app.
And when it takes off,
all I got to do is sue him.
It's fool-proof.
You're programming now,
Abed?
Didn't get any work with
your four-year film degree?
One job,
directing a commercial.
Still haven't been paid.
I'll cut you
a check tomorrow,
but just so we're clear,
you quit.
Creative differences.
I asked you to put
the phone number on
the screen.
I didn't like the number.
555? It's derivative.
It's the number
of my business.
It sounds fake.
How can every number
start with 555?
Are there only
10,000 numbers?
Abed, you quit?
You said you got fired.
You haven't paid rent in our
apartment in two months.
Well, why don't you
sell him a pill
that will help him
give up on his dreams?
Relaxabrex doesn't make you
give up on your dreams.
That's a side effect.
At least the drugs I sell
don't get slurped
out of my belly button.
That's only on
Tummy Tuesdays!
Oh, it's okay...
Oh, I'm sorry...
Andre left again.
It's...it's not like
last time.
He's staying with family.
He took the boys.
He took the dog.
He took the D.V.R.
166 episodes of  Bones
just gone.
It was my fault this time.
I cheated on him
with Shirley's sandwiches.
I threw the money
into expanding.
I just didn't think
I could fail.
Okay.
Well, just so you know,
this is the sort of stuff
that someone could use
to make a claim
against a school.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
I have to go
to the bathroom again.
While I'm gone,
I want you to think about
what I said
as an exercise.
Do you guys feel weird
about doing this without...
Magnitude?
That's everything
you asked for.
Who are you flipping?
My friends,
who are now
the Save Greendale Committee,
which I created.
Oh.
Classic Winger.
I forgot what it was like
to be good at being bad.
So just close the deal
and bring it home
to daddy, eh?
Oh, sorry, Alan.
Change of daddies.
I'll take it from here.
No, no, but it's my case.
Humphries was your case.
Jeff...
You're scaring me.
Good.
Guys like you should be
more scared.
You trust-funded,
body-sprayed,
Eli-Roth-DVD owner...
You're an amateur
monster, Alan,
and you stomp in the grave
of a real monster
who was willing
to stay buried
because real monsters
have shame,
because they wish that...
You're not the monologue.
Give me your tie.
What?
No monologue for you.
Give me your tie.
That's for making me go
to this school.
That's for making
the last four years happen.
And now I get to make
them un-happen
for me and the only people
I care about.
(WHIMPERING)
I failed my husband.
I failed my kids.
I've failed  Bones.
I'm helping to hook
a whole new battle
of little Annies
on Adderall.
I've been spending
so much time with computers,
your tears are just ones
and zeroes to me.
Yeah, you were a real
Hallmark card before.
I'm much sadder
than the rest of you.
(SNIFFLING)
I will figure out
why later.
Jeff, full disclosure.
Our lives are worse than
the day we got here.
Well, that is
a serious allegation
to arrive at all
by yourselves.
Are you sure?
Yes.
And we've come
to a decision as a group,
and please don't judge us
for suggesting it.
Hey, I'll back you up
no matter what.
We decided to re-enroll
at Greendale.
What? Are you nuts?
(ALL CHANTING)
Greendale! Greendale!
You guys want to
keep it down?
(ALL SCREAM)
Chang?
Kevin?
Chang.
I've dropped
the amnesia thing,
copped to my crimes,
and went to jail.
Now I'm on work release.
Working as what?
Math teacher.
Next, explain the pajamas.
Well, I'm on work release
from house arrest,
but I don't have a home.
See this?
This won't let me travel
100 yards from this,
and this only has
a 30-yard cord,
so I can only travel...
Whatever.
You do the math.
You said you teach math.
Exactly, I teach it.
You do it.
Chang was faking
his Changnesia?
They seriously rehired
a teacher
they fired for trying
to burn down the school?
After being rehired
as a security guard
after being fired for
impersonating a teacher.
That's insane,
and I'm Abed.
Worse than insane.
Irresponsible.
Evil.
I don't believe in evil.
But this school clearly
got a finger up its butt
as a child.
This place ruins lives.
If that were true,
then what could we
possibly do about it?
(SLOW CLAPPING)
(GROANS)
Make 'em dance, Winger.
Ew, Jeff, what's your evil
old legal nemesis doing here?
Nemesis?
No, we were partners again
until I lost my usefulness.
I may be evil,
but your friend here is
so much more dangerous.
Tell 'em how it took you
30 minutes
to make them think
they wanted to sue
their own school.
(GASPS)
I did it. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry.
Anyway, I'll leave you
to pick up these pieces.
I'm gonna go
score some blow.
My dealer's
a gym teacher here.
(CHUCKLES)
You were lying to us?
I never lied to you.
I showed you
the right truth.
Britta, when we met,
you were
an eclectic anarchist.
How did you become
the group's airhead?
Thank you?
And, Shirley,
you've gone from
an independent divorcee
striking out on her own
to a bankrupt fry cook hoping
for a call from her husband.
Troy, your entire identity
has been consumed
by your relationship
with another man.
You found my
Clive Owen Tumblr.
And what happened to Annie
the unstoppable go-getter?
Well, there was that
gas leak last year.
Oh, don't blame it all
on the gas leak year.
This was
a four-year process.
We went in one end
as real people
and out the other end
as mixed-up cartoons.
Cool.
Sure.
This coming from
the guy who's had
how many psychotic breaks
on campus?
Are we including
the gas leak year?
You all came here with
a chance to be something,
and you all had that
taken away from you.
Get something back.
Seek damages.
Sign here.
But you're our hero.
I mean, in the commercial...
The commercial was a lie.
You staged a robot fight?
Yeah.
In real life,
the robot wins.
Troy?
If Jeff didn't change,
then Jeff is right.
Case closed.
Let's make some money.
Okay, Jeff, if this is what
you really want to do.
I'll sign.
The choice to make is yours.
No, it's yours.
We're putting Greendale
in your hands.
Do we all have
to say something?
No, you can
just sign it.
Okay.
You brought us together.
With lies.
But what you do is
above lying, remember?
You show us the right truth.
You won't regret this.
(ALL CHEER HALFHEARTEDLY)
I'd like to take
the study room table
in back and burn it.
Burn it? Why?
The same reason
I never returned  Time Bandits
to blockbuster.
Nobody else deserves it.
Jesus!
Looks as if you've lost
your way.
Pierce?
Continue on this path,
and you might miss
your last chance
to see the Pierce Hawthorne
Museum of gender sensitivity
and sexual potency
on the central quad.
The museum and this hologram
were donated in compliance
with a court order
I'm not allowed to discuss.
Let's just say some women
can't take a compliment.
Unbelievable.
What I am allowed
to discuss is Greendale,
and I'll say this.
Don't turn your back on it.
Take it from a man with
no legal right to be there.
You're in a special place.
A crappy place, sure,
but only because it gives
crappy people a chance
to sort themselves out.
Did I sound gay
at the end?
Do you want to do
another take?
Ah!
Jeffrey, I'm not decent.
I know.
These are the signatures
of the five people
that are crazy enough
to care about this toilet.
And tonight, I almost
got them to sue it.
Heed the warning!
It's not easy being dean,
Jeffrey!
Then stop being the dean!
It's my whole ideantity!
I mean, wah,
see what I did there?
That's proof!
Get your crap together.
Your job is not
to hand out degrees.
Your job is to
make this a toilet
that people don't have
to be crazy to care about.
But you could stay here
and help me save the school.
For how much money?
I, I can't offer you
any money.
I could offer you a job.
You just described slavery.
I mean, there's nothing
in the budget
for school saver,
but I could hire you as...
(SIGHS)
Screw you, Abed.
I'd be depressed right now
if these samples from work
weren't giving me
a new outlook on life.
If you're interested
in learning more,
ask your doctor
if Joyvatrex
is right for you.
Oh, honey.
If we sue Greendale,
can I be
a surprise witness?
Wait. Don't tell me.
Stop!
We shouldn't
sue the school.
Oh.
Come on!
Are you trying to give us
emotional whiplash?
Look, if you feel
there's more work to be
done on yourselves,
then as crappy
as this place is,
it's a place that
you can do it.
You got a job
teaching here,
didn't you?
I don't want
to talk about it.
Well, then,
I'm getting back into
forensic science.
That was my actual dream.
It's my fault
I bailed on it.
A film degree doesn't
make me a filmmaker.
I need to learn how to work
with other people.
I need to figure out
who I am.
I'll help you.
Get out of my brain.
I need to learn how
to really run a business
by my own standards,
not Greendale's.
I'm gonna get
a four-year psych degree,
then a master's,
and become
a real psychologist.
Or you could find
another major.
A real psychologist.
How about English?
Psychology.
All right,
what's important is,
no matter what,
we'll be trying
to talk Britta into doing
something different
together.
(CHUCKLES)
Burn, hopelessness.
(ALL SCREAM)
We got this.
Oh, my god, be careful!
(BOTH YELLING)
MAN:  Little victories count
for a lot around here...
Wow, this is good.
Even if you never asked
to win in the first place.
And you have to enjoy those
nice moments while you can.
See, he does
a voice-over wrap-up
at the end of
every episode.
Wow.
Cool.
Because around here,
they never last very long.
Once more.
More teachery.
I want to kill myself.
Use that.
Are you a good person?
Yes, unlike you.
I can guarantee
the Winger beaten you.
Not anymore.
(DRAMATIC ROCK MUSIC)
(FARTS)
(LAUGHS)