Hi, everybody, I'm Jeff...
Um, Mr. Winger,
and this is
Fundamentals of Law.
Any questions?
You, red hair.
I'm not gonna learn names.
Will there be a syllabus?
"Will there be a syllabus?"
Is good example
of a question. Moving on.
Ski cap.
How are we gonna be graded?
Oh, no spoilers, ski cap.
Maybe we better do names.
Dave.
What percent of our grade
will the final be?
Come on, guys, percentages,
grades, that syllabus thing...
Are we human beings or just
question-and-answer machines?
We're students.
And you're a teacher.
Yeah.
I'm a teacher.
[♪♪♪]
Did you see that?
That teacher just leered at me.
GIRL: Ew.
Hey, look, it's
the star of Head of the ass.
Shut up, Leonard! Nice earring.
You look like the road manager
for the California Raisins.
Whoa!
What kind of teacher
talks to a student
like that?
Right?
GIRL: Yeah.
Fresh meat, huh?
Yeah, Jeff Winger, Law.
Buzz Hickey,
Criminology.
You can have that half
of the office, but come spring,
that corner is stacked to
the rafters with fetal pigs.
I won't be here that long.
This is a temporary gig for me.
Mmm, I get it.
Teaching to make ends meet
until a real job comes along.
Yeah, me too.
Oh, cool.
How long have you been...
15 years. Ha, ha, ha.
15 years and counting.
Heh-heh.
"Temporary gig."
Ha, ha, ha.
Oh, I like you.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one they all
Just fade away ♪
Oh, the new table
turned out great, Abed.
Splendid varnishing.
"Table mark II"?
I added that,
and a few custom upgrades.
It's voice activated.
Table, resume table mode.
Huh?
Oh.
Mmm.
Table, power down.
Wait!
I got a cup on there.
ANNIE: Oh, teacher man!
SHIRLEY: Ee!
It's Professor Winger!
Mr. Winger.
Please don't razz me
about being a teacher.
Teaching is the most noble
profession in the world.
Yeah, tell that to the guy
that shares my office.
He fixes
cuckoo clocks for fun.
That sounds like Mr. Hickey,
my Criminology professor.
I certainly hope you'll be
a better teacher than him.
Annie, I don't know Law.
I wasn't a real lawyer,
remember?
I can't just pretend
I'm teaching.
I'm not Mythbusters.
[ABED GASPS]
Two-day course called
"Nicolas Cage: Good or bad."
I'm signing up.
I've always wanted to know.
Nicolas Cage is one of pop
culture's greatest mysteries.
There's a course on Cage,
but if you mention
Jesus to your science teacher,
you get a written warning.
Well, Jesus wasn't
in 70 movies.
I'm in.
Cage class, sounds fun.
Jeff, you don't have time
to take a blow-off class.
You need to figure out
what you're gonna teach.
Thanks, for one glorious second,
I forgot I was a teacher.
[HUMMING
"POMP AND CIRCUMSTANCE"]
[CONTINUES HUMMING]
Oh! Look at
Mr. Smarty Pants!
Ha, ha, ha.
I am so excited!
Jeff is gonna help me
save the school.
Not all by himself.
I am learning Excel.
Jeff, do you know Excel?
No.
Well, it looks like you do.
Ha, ha, ha.
Yay, teaching!
I, as you know, am Dramatic
professor Sean Garrity,
and you are now embarking
on an odyssey of discussion
about an actor
who keeps the world asking,
Nicolas Cage, good or bad?
Yes, young man?
So you don't know?
Mr. Nadir.
Mr. Nadir drove
our TV Studies professor
out of his mind by proving
that there was an answer
to the question
"Who's the boss?"
Angela.
I admire your brain, Mr. Nadir.
I did not admire
Professor Sheffield,
but I promise you,
this question has no answer.
Your homework is to watch
five Nicolas Cage films
by Wednesday, no marathons.
Space out your viewings.
Five, that's it?
Be careful,
Abed Nadir.
Promise me
you will be careful.
I have no idea
how to make a curriculum.
Becoming a teacher
was a huge mistake.
Without a doubt.
That said, there are
certain perks.
Excuse me.
Didn't know teachers could cut.
I can actually experience
this food warm and disgusting.
Winger,
what are you doing?
This line is for food,
not for Lionel Richie tickets.
[LAUGHTER]
This is my house.
Come here.
This man's name
is Mr. Winger,
and Mr. Winger
is a teacher.
You know what that means?
It means
he gets your meatballs.
Ah, please.
That's all I have.
Get outta here.
Place is a zoo.
The trick is,
you gotta show
the other baboons
you got a bigger,
redder ass.
Let's hit the lounge.
[SOFT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
Whoa.
Everybody, this is
the new guy, Winger.
He's having trouble
planning his curriculum.
[LAUGHTER]
What?
Here's all
you need to know.
Break into groups,
grade each other's papers,
and please enjoy the seven-disk
edition of Planet Earth.
[KNOCK AT THE DOOR]
PELTON: Yoo-hoo!
Is there a Mr. Winger
in here? Heh-heh.
Jeffrey, we need to carve out
some time to learn Excel.
Do you guys know Excel?
I'm learning.
You know the rules, Pelton.
Drop the checks and move on.
I'm gonna boot up my computer
and download the tutor...
[LAUGHTER]
What was that about?
Union rules.
Management's not allowed
in the faculty lounge.
I could get used to this.
[NICOLAS CAGE YELLING
AND FIGHTING]
Nicolas Cage
is so weird.
I mean, he seemed scared
to smell that flower
but happy to get shot.
He's a complex performer.
He'll give you The Rock,
Con Air, then Face/Off,
and you think you understand,
but then Windtalkers,
Guarding Tess, The Wicker Man.
He begs you to stop watching,
but you can't.
[NICOLAS CAGE YELLING]
That was
an odd choice.
Would you say it was
odd good or odd bad?
Maybe he's just good
in good movies
and then acts crazy in crap
to make drug money.
But is he good,
or is he bad?
Every actor is something.
Robert Downey Jr., good,
Jim Belushi, bad.
Van Damme,
the good kind of bad,
Johnny Depp,
the bad kind of good.
There's a spectrum,
and Cage is on it.
I just have to find him.
I'm gonna go
check on Jeff.
Oh.
[LINE RINGING]
JEFF: Hello.
Hey, Jeff, how's the old
curriculum going?
Great. Consider our nation's
youth pre-inspired.
Want a refill, Winger?
Mmm.
Is that Hickey?
Yeah.
We're working on syllabuses.
Hey, let's turd
some lockers!
[ALL CHEERING]
Gotta go! Teacher thing!
It's "syllabi."
Guterman.
Droppin' mad science?
Ooh, Elaine, take it easy
on the Oxford commas.
Hey, walk, don't run, Mister!
This isn't a racetrack!
Okay, dangerous minds,
let's break into groups,
discuss chapter one,
and if you are lucky,
we might sneak in
a little Planet Earth.
Any questions?
Ahem.
Just a few.
Ah, she in your class, yo!
So I guess, just...
Read chapter one.
And memorize the federal rules
of civil procedure.
Class dismissed.
Not so fast, Jeff.
I assume you know why
I'm keeping you after class.
Not really.
Ski cap and white Dave
got lots of stuff
wrong too.
You're the teacher, Jeff.
You don't have to rub it in.
What I saw today
was embarrassing.
[SCOFFS]
You were late, had no idea...
Hey! You had no idea
what tort reform meant,
and when I asked you
to explain the sixth amendment,
you pled the fifth!
I know my rights.
No, you don't.
That's the problem.
Here.
I gathered some materials.
Tomorrow morning,
before class,
I need to verify that
you know enough to teach.
You're gonna quiz me?
You're the worst.
I wish Troy was in my class
instead of you!
I hate her, I hate her,
I hate her, I hate her, I hate
her, I hate her, I hate her.
Hey, wait, I warned you
to separate these worlds.
She's lead,
we're chalk.
She needs to be taken out.
Of your class.
I say minus her.
Minus her?
Give her A-minuses.
It'll drive her nuts,
she'll drop.
She'll call me on it.
She'll report me.
Teachers don't have
to explain minuses.
Why do you think
we invented 'em?
She's my friend.
Eh.
You like
the Leonard meatballs?
They added
something special.
It's Leonard.
[LAUGHS]
Come on, I'm just
messing with you.
You done with your bit?
I'd like my earring back.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Go get your earring,
you piece of human garbage.
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHTER AND CHATTER]
Uh...
[GASPS]
Oh, my God.
Okay, hey,
I have a working theory,
and don't react until
you've heard the whole thing.
If you watch closely, at the
seven-minute mark in Snake Eyes,
you'll notice the moment
where an alien arm
could've come up and...
Abed, this isn't worth it.
Maybe Nicolas Cage
is just...
Crazy.
All actors are crazy, Annie.
Some crazy actors are good,
some are bad,
but none of them are neither.
There's no such thing as both,
so which one is...
[NICOLAS CAGE VOICE]
Nicolas Cage, huh? Oh! Oh!
Okay, so break into groups,
and then, you guys
quiz each other.
Mr. Winger, is that really
the best use of our time?
Seems like the value
of having you here is...
I think my value as a teacher
is to teach you how to learn.
You're telling us
teach ourselves.
I don't think you'll learn
if I tell you.
If you tell us what you think,
we'll learn that.
I thought you should
break into groups,
but you failed to learn that,
so your theory's invalid.
[STUDENTS JEERING AND LAUGHING]
BOY: Ooh, snap.
Break into groups.
Mr. Winger, how did you do that?
Do what?
You won an argument
against Annie Edison.
You don't argue
with Annie, Garrett,
you let her argue
with herself until she loses.
You can win by not arguing?
Yeah, ski cap.
Anyone that tries
to argue has already lost,
because they pick
an argument to lose.
I mean, that's why
I never lost a case.
Prosecutors beat themselves,
because they-- Here.
Because they draw a circle
around something
called "the truth,"
and they say that everything
outside it is a lie.
[♪♪♪]
JEFF:
Annie,
don't cry,
you were right.
I actually might
enjoy teaching.
I'm not crying
because of you.
I got this from
Professor Hickey.
What the hell?
He gave you a dead rat?
No, this is my witness
intimidation project.
He gave me this.
JEFF: A-minus.
I guess I overextended
my schedule.
I'm sorry, Jeff.
I have to drop your class.
Okay, thoughts
on Nicolas Cage.
I think he's a genius.
I mean, he keeps getting hired
for some reason, and it's not
because of his hair.
I don't know, if I was
in 70 films over 30 years,
and I spent each one
talking at random volumes,
I might accidentally
win an Oscar.
I think our opinions about
pop culture are fed to us
by machines designed
to criminalize
human autonomy.
Good one.
Dear God.
Abed.
No, stand back.
Give him space.
[♪♪♪]
Nicolas Cage, good or bad.
A challenge, certainly,
but not unsolvable,
because all actors
have distinct values,
which I use
to find answers.
Abed, how much
Nicolas Cage did you--
Enough!
I watched enough to find...
Heh-heh. The answers.
Ha, ha. Because this...
This is my reality,
this is how I learned to be,
and my being doesn't
allow for Nicolas...
[NICOLAS CAGE VOICE]
Freaking Cage, okay?
Oh, yeah!
Ha, ha.
Yeah! Oh! Oh!
[YELLING LIKE NICOLAS CAGE]
Oh, I'm a cat.
I'm a sexy cat.
[LAUGHING]
Oh! Oh! Oh!
O-o-oh!
Abed? Think of
something safe,
like Holly Hunter
or Don Cheadle!
[FOOTSTEPS RUNNING]
Abed? Abed!
That was brilliant.
JEFF:
You gave Annie an A-minus?
How could you?
What were you thinking?
Are you drawing a peanut?
It's a duck, and it's none
of your concern, actually.
Are you trying to cartoon?
Trying and succeeding.
State your business.
I want to know
what kind of monster
minuses the best student
in his class.
I'm a monster? I was
in the storm drain lair
of the Black River ripper.
I have seen human heads used
for things other than heads,
so you best not be
calling me a monster.
Okay, you're a bad teacher.
I got her off your back.
I was handling it.
Unlike you, I know
how to engage my students.
I mean, I may not
love teaching,
but I did fool around
with it today,
and I may hook up with it
again a few more times
even if I do dump it
right before Christmas.
We do not work for them.
Maybe we do.
That does not count
as an argument.
Yeah, well, drawing ducks
doesn't count as cartooning!
It's one duck,
his name is Jim,
and publishers
are interested!
Miss Edison, good news.
I talked to Professor Hickey,
and it turns out
your project was an "A."
You used your connections
to change my grade?
No, an A-minus means
you actually earned an "A,"
but the teacher
doesn't like you.
It's a secret faculty thing.
What?
Are you kidding?
Et tu, brute?
Am I using that right?
I've been busting my butt
for five years,
and the whole thing
comes down
to a few old losers'
petty insecurities?
Oligarchy!
Et tu, brute!
We've got to tell people!
TROY: Mmm.
Minuses are made up!
It's riot time! Yeah!
Ugh!
Bring me their heads!
[SCREAMS]
Pop, pop!
[ALL SCREAMING]
Abed? I couldn't find you
at school, so I got worried.
You're throwing away
all your little movies, why?
They have no value
anymore.
Well, if you're looking
for something to believe in,
I know a skinny, little Hebrew
handyman you could meet.
I'm not going to become
Christian, Shirley,
or a better Muslim.
This was my religion.
I thought the meaning of people
was somewhere in here.
Then I looked inside Nicolas
Cage and I found a secret.
People are random
and pointless.
Well, in my religion,
the whole point
is that you can't understand
every little thing,
and you know, there's a word
for people who remind you
that you're not God, and invite
you to try a little harder.
Prophets, messiahs,
kung fu pandas.
So Nicolas Cage is Jesus?
Uh, no,
but he clearly works
in mysterious ways,
and maybe that's just his job.
And that's why critics can
call him a genius or an idiot
and be right
no matter what.
A demon to some and an angel
to others, like a Cenobite.
Excuse me,
did you say Cenobite?
Yeah, you know, Cenobite,
like from Hellraiser.
You like Hellraiser?
You know the word "hellraiser"?
I thought pinhead in space
was a bit of a letdown,
but I'm in for the ride.
[YELLING AND FIGHTING]
Rise up, Greendale!
Your teachers have been
lying to you!
You deserve
slightly higher grades!
ALL:
Slightly higher grades!
The whole world
is watching this!
GIRL: Yeah!
Wait. I'm out of data minutes.
The world will be watching this
on the first of next month!
ALL:
Slightly higher grades!
Jeffrey, do something!
Slightly higher grades.
Distract them.
Take your shirt off!
Here.
ALL: Slightly higher grades!
Slightly higher grades!
Everybody,
calm down! Just listen!
Do you think the students
and teachers at Harvard
are at each other's throats?
No, because
they're all rich.
We all have something
in common too.
We all suck.
We're all broke.
We just went
through an entire week
of meatball lunches
without even blinking.
Oh, that's on me.
I converted the lunch menu
to a spreadsheet.
The teachers here
are teachers here
because they did something
wrong, same as the students.
So get on the same team,
because, take it from me,
those of us that get to leave
aren't going anywhere.
ALL: Boo!
No, you suck!
[ALL JEERING]
Ugh!
Jeffrey, go with my
"take off your shirt" plan!
May I point out that
you're doing this together?
It's all based on rows
and columns of cells.
I think that's why
the call it "Excel."
I don't care.
Mmm-kay,
now, I know
it's unrealistic
to think that we can
eliminate riots completely,
but I have been
crunching the numbers,
and I believe we can
reduce them by 40%.
Let's hope the man
doesn't target you
for dreaming this big.
Here's my plan.
That "Save Greendale" Committee
you pretended to form?
We need one of those for real.
I want a student-teacher
alliance, with you in charge.
I vote myself out.
You don't have a quorum.
And don't forget,
if I fire you,
you're likely to starve
and die, so you know.
Do you want me
to cut your meatball?
[CLEARS THROAT]
All right, look,
there are two things
I don't do well,
apologies
and drawing duck bills.
I lost perspective.
Students aren't the enemy,
and, I don't know, maybe
my bills are a little pointy.
Maybe I'm basing them
on beaks.
Apologize to Annie.
I did, I gave her an "A."
I don't know how else
to make it right.
Oh. I guess,
I don't know, I quit.
I got a better idea.
As our first order
of business
for the student-teacher
Save Greendale Committee,
we hereby ban the dean
from attending future meetings.
ALL: Yeah.
Our second order of business.
Lunch.
Yeah.
[HICKEY CLEARS THROAT]
I'm taste-testing rations
for the shelter I'm digging.
Are you the coolest
person in the world?
I doubt it.
I would like to address the fact
there are no Asian-Americans
represented here.
We can get Chang.
No need to rush into anything,
I just wanted to address it.
Anybody want some nuts?
[ACOUSTIC MUSIC
SUNG IN FRENCH]
Quiet, I think
Jeff's coming.
This is gonna be hilarious.
[GROANS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Yeah, pharmacy please.
Yeah, this is Buzz Hickey.
I think you gave me
the wrong medication.
I usually get Lipitor.
What do you mean my insurance
won't cover it anymore?
My body doesn't respond well
to the generic stuff.
Let me ask you
a question, lady,
can you pay out of pocket?
I'm an educator, ma'am,
living on a teacher's salary!
No, I, I'm sorry.
What's your name?
Leia, well, let me
tell you something, Leia,
I wake up every night
screaming.
Life is unfair, but
it's the only thing we g...
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I'll call back later.
Mom, it's Buzz. I'm gonna
say this as fast as I can.
We can't afford to bury Dad
with the rest of the family.
MAN:
Did you get any of that?