(THUNDER)
(GIGGLES)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Oh.
Please stay for
complimentary saltines
and full-price sodas.
But first, the dulcet tones
of the Bennett boys.
BOTH:
♪ When you were here before
♪ Couldn't look you
in the eye
(THUNDER)
♪ You're just like an angel
♪ Your skin makes me cry
Bro, free crackers.
Want to spend your life
opening lockers?
You don't have to
raise your voice!
I'm going as fast
as I can!
BOTH:
♪ You float like a feather
Oh, great, now I have
these folders to deal with!
Et tu, pencil?
♪ In a beautiful world ♪
When it rains, it pours.
BOTH:
♪ I wish I was special ♪
(GASPS)
(DISTANT SCREAM)
Ass Crack Bandit!
(SCREAMING IN CROWD)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: Let's settle down!
Guys, what is known...
What's known is that
around noon yesterday,
an unidentified student
dropped a coin
in another student's,
you know, upper buttock fold.
(CLAMORING)
Yes, yes.
Gwen Ridley,
Greendale Gazette.
Is this the return
of the Ass Crack Bandit?
Okay, that person, Gwen,
if he ever existed,
stopped being active
over a year ago.
(CLAMOR)
Yeah.
Tim Briggs,
Breendale Mirror.
Is it true that
after the attack,
you received a letter
from the Ass Crack Bandit?
I never said that, Tim,
and when did we split
The Gazette from  The Mirror?
And how many photographs
do you people need?
Raul Lopez,  Las Noticias
Hispanicas De Greendale.
Will this affect soccer?
(CROWD CLAMORING)
We did, in fact,
receive a letter
an hour after
the incident.
Including details
not known to the public
about the brand
of Garrett's underwear.
Hanes his ways.
"I am the Ass Crack Bandit.
"Humans make better
banks than piggies.
"Whenever I get more
change at the store,
"I can't wait to drop it
down your butts.
"I think I will go
to the bank and get
so much change
"and take all my dollars
and make them into change
"and drop it
all down there."
He should be called
"The Run-On Sentence Bandit."
From this moment, people,
we are at DEFCON 4.
If that's the
highest DEFCON,
and if high DEFCONs
are worse than low ones.
Ah, you all
remember psychology
Professor Duncan.
Hey, buddy.
Where'd you go?
I was taking care
of my sick mother.
She's still alive,
but I've put in my time.
Britta.
Oh, Pierce, good for you.
I always thought
that hairpiece
was a bit cowardly.
Duncan is going to help us
work up something
called a "profile."
So we can root
this student out.
For the record, I tried
to get something done
about this two years ago.
This is not about you, Annie.
This is about the school.
This is the biggest PR.
Crisis to hit Greendale
since we held that rally
protesting the wrong Korea.
Jeffrey, how can you help?
I'll take a look
at the whole picture,
see if any pieces match up.
(AUTOMATED WOMAN VOICE)
Double fruit bonus.
(VIDEO GAME SOUND EFFECTS)
MAN:  Crikey! Kiwi combo, mate.
I took a map
of the campus
and pinpointed
all the locations
of the Ass Crack
Bandit strikes.
MAN:  You can't
handle the fruit.
During the bandit's
most daring spree,
he cracked three
people in a row.
Today, I sprinted
between all three sites.
My quickest time
was 20 minutes.
The ACB, did it in 10.
So he's got long legs.
I think he has something
I don't, a shortcut.
The faculty lounge.
You think the bandit's
a teacher?
The dean's not gonna
help me pursue this.
I need help.
MAN:  Pineapple penalty, fool!
No! Unfair and racist.
Look, no way, Annie.
Look, the faculty already
hates me, and the dean
signs my paychecks.
But this is important!
I can assure you
that's not true.
MAN:  Fruit, fruit,
fruit, fruit, fruit!
Collect the seeds, sucka!
(ANSWERING MACHINE)
After the tone,
please leave a message.
(BEEP)
Hey, Abed. Lab ran late.
What'd Annie get us
for dinner?
I hope it's not salad again.
(CREAKING)
I'd rather just stop
at the meat store.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
All right.
Talk to you later.
Oh.
Well, hello.
(THUNDER)
Oh!
(RADIO CHATTER)
(GAGS)
Will you stop
with the cups
and the blankets?
This is how they
comfort victims
in movies.
Okay, I am hereby
banning change
from this campus.
You really think
that's an effective...
Well, guess what,
your two cents is change,
and it's banned.
Got something.
Frankie, somebody
get me a bag.
Oh, give me that.
"I hope you enjoyed
my work again.
"You can't stop me,
because what are
you gonna do,
"not have butts?" Oof.
Dean, I think it's a teacher.
I beg your what?
I have evidence
that shows...
Yeah, and I have
evidence that shows
I'm not listening.
Exhibit "A," exhibit "B."
La la la la la la.
(SCOFFS)
This is never
gonna end
if you keep choosing
politics over justice.
Okay, you want to
make trouble?
Go to Parker brothers.
You're out.
(SCOFFS)
Take it easy.
Taking it easy is
how Troy ended up
with a quarter of
a buck in his crack.
Annie, nobody's asking
you to do this...
Jeff, come on!
You know how this
school works.
We do it,
or it doesn't get done.
The men on our coins
understood that.
Maybe the Ass
Crack Bandit's point
is that we're letting
our values slide.
Or maybe he's
a frat boy coming
from the laundromat.
The important question
is "Who cares?"
(SCOFFS)
Look,
let me know what
you need from me,
on the down low.
Way down low.
(SQUEALS QUIETLY)
And no squealing.
Okay, squeal.
(SQUEALS LOUDLY)
(ON RADIO)  Real Neil here,
five days into the return
of the Ass Crack Bandit.
MAN:  It's alive!
NEIL:  Since we last spoke,
three more victims
have caught the quarter,
with no end in sight.
Safety pants,
100 bucks a pop.
All sandwiches $5.
Sorry, no change.
Blame the bandit.
Here's a song that's been
shooting up the request line
faster than coins
are dropping.
♪ It said quarter to five
♪ But it was quarter to ass
♪ You thought your
plumbing was safe
♪ But your jeans
were half-mast
♪ Another coin
down the drain
♪ Now, that's some change
that won't last ♪
The nature of the Ass
Crack Bandit's crimes
would suggest
that he's angry or
just fell in love.
We know that he hates
money or loves it
or doesn't care about
money and hates butts
or loves them.
Mmm. Abed,
you're special.
Can't you just
stand at the scene
of the crime and see
what happened?
Yeah.
(EERIE MUSIC)
I see a man,
using a social disorder
as a procedural device.
Wait, wait, wait,
I see another man.
Mildly autistic super
detectives everywhere.
Basic cable,
broadcast networks.
Pain. Painful writing.
It hurts.
Okay, ooh, la la.
Hickey, what have you got?
Heartburn. It doesn't
help me catch criminals.
Okay. I didn't want
to take drastic measures,
but I've cooked up
a little something.
Chang?
(WHISTLING)
You better put a quarter
in that crack, Mr. Bandit.
Professor Hickey.
(GROANS)
CHANG: Whoops.
Hah! Gotcha!
Whoa! Ha,
what do you think?
I think this is spending
too much money on a crime
that nets you
25 cents a pop.
Ah, no, no.
This was free.
Then I think you just
admitted you already
owned a fake butt.
"I am the mad hatter,
if hats were butts.
"I am neither left nor right.
I am the space between.
"To me, you're all like ants
"marching to class,
freaks on parade."
I mean, why mix metaphors?
Ants don't have butts.
Wait a minute.
Ants do have butts.
No.
These are Dave lyrics.
Dave?
Dave Matthews.
Hard-core fans
call him Dave.
Oh, excuse me for being
alive in the '90s
and having two ears
connected to a heart.
Okay, so all we need to do
is assemble a list
of which Greendale teachers
are Dave Matthews fans.
Guess we better
get to work.
(BACH'S  SUITE NO. 3 PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
Done.
Oh.
Thought that would
take longer.
TROY: So please
approve the dean's
new security measure
called "Troy's Law"
because a camera
in the bathroom...
...is better than
a quarter in your butt.
(APPLAUSE)
As we've seen,
the Ass Crack Bandit
can be defeated
by using the three "B"s,
belts, briefs
and buddies. Good.
The bandit always
gets his victims
when they're alone.
Bend over with friends over.
There's safety in numbers.
(SCREAMS)
I got cracked!
He's under the bleachers!
Everyone remain calm,
please!
All right,
free-for-all!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Hey. Where you been?
I questioned Guterman.
We can cross him off.
At the time of
the first cracking,
he was chaperoning
Greendale's science dance.
The student that attended
can vouch for him.
I checked out
Mrs. Plimpton.
Airtight alibi.
She's dead.
Next on my list is this one.
Bublitz.
We're close,
I can feel it.
CHANG: Mmm!
This extra-long
churro tastes good
in my real mouth.
Nom nom nom nom nom.
May I help you?
We'd like to ask
you a few questions.
If that's okay.
He's bolting!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
He's there!
If you're going to
confiscate this,
know one thing.
It's a mild, kind sativa,
perfect for playing guitar.
There's been
another...
What the hell?
Destroying classrooms?
Secretly investigating
teachers behind my back?
Someone has to
investigate the faculty,
but you're like a
single-celled organism,
no nerve.
Annie, you're suspended.
Wait, you can't do that!
Don't tell me
what I can't do.
What do you think you are,
Cosmo's July quiz?
She was trying
to help you.
Let me ask you two something.
Let me be, like,
the 50th person at
this school to ask,
what is this, huh?
What is this
creepy business?
BOTH: What?
I think you two
like to partner up
on cutesy capers
so you can hold hands
in the dark
and address your urges
in semi-acceptable scenarios.
Whoa, not cool!
You not cool!
You unprofessional!
I'm punishing you, Jeffrey.
Starting next week,
you are the new coach
of the water polo team.
BOTH: What?
That's right.
Every morning,
in the water...
(PHONE RINGING)
Mmm.
Craig Pelton,
dean and assistant
water polo coach.
What?
(DISTORTED)
This is the Ass Crack Bandit.
Uh...
(SNAPPING FINGERS)
I find it funny
that you ever thought
you could catch me.
Oh, that's very interesting.
Please continue.
I've enjoyed our game
of cat and mouse.
It's funny how close
your two little helpers
came to catching me.
I liked watching
them run in circles.
Although sometimes I wonder,
are they chasing me
as an excuse to
get near each other?
I mean, get a room already.
We're friends!
Why don't you tell
us where you are,
and we'll discuss it?
I am the bringer of change.
I am the filler of cracks.
Oh, that's very interesting.
I myself was in 4H.
(CLICKS AND DIAL TONE)
Oh!
Trace the call, Rhonda!
(SNAPPING)
This means trace the call!
Look at the extension.
594. Okay.
Tracing...
Tracing.
Got it, the stables!
We have stables?
Let's go.
(ANNIE GRUNTS)
Creepy.
PELTON: I don't know.
Add some doilies
and a foot bath,
and this is
my mom's house.
STAR-BURNS: Mush! Mush!
Mush! Yah! Mush!
No, run. Mush! Mush!
Star-Burns?
(SIGHS)
(CATS MEOWING)
Since faking his death
to escape meth charges,
Alex "Star-Burns"
Osbourne,
has been living
in the stables,
eating garbage,
and trying to
build a cat car.
He's also confessed
to dropping coins
down exposed butt cracks.
Case closed.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
High five?
Sure.
No.
Oh, American
high five. Sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
Whoo!
(APPLAUSE DIES DOWN)
WOMAN: Oh!
MAN: Ooh!
So much pain.
But now it's time to heal!
You're all invited
to the official
"We caught the
Ass Crack Bandit"
dance tonight
in the cafeteria!
(APPLAUSE)
Jeff!
There's no way
Star-Burns did it.
Innocent people
don't confess.
Are you kidding me?
You knew it was a teacher.
You know that doesn't add up.
Maybe I was wrong.
Or maybe the dean
was right about us.
What? No.
Annie, I took
this case because
I wanted to help you.
Then what is this?
It's platonic shoulder
holding. Look.
Leonard, hello,
how are you?
It's a guy who
puts quarters down
butt cracks, Jeff.
Let's just let it go.
(SIGHS)
We can do better.
STAR-BURNS:
Aah! Change is money!
What are you guys,
millionaires?
T-shirts here!
Cracked but not
broken, huh?
Who's in? T-shirts!
T-shirts here!
20 bucks.
Professor Duncan?
Yeah?
Not going to the dance?
I'll go later.
Oh, actually, would you
mind coming and getting me
when Britta's drunk?
Listen, as Britta's friend,
I should give you this ad...
(DAVE MATTHEWS BAND'S
ANTS MARCHING PLAYING)
Yes! That is
my jam right there.
Dave Matthews fan?
Obviously you're not.
Real fans call him Dave.
STAR-BURNS:
♪ Bum Bum Bum ♪
I've heard this song before.
Hey, winger, who is this?
What are you talking about?
You don't know who this is?
I remember it from the '90s.
♪ Hee Haw Haw Haw
Hee haw haw ♪
It's Dave.
Lee Roth?
You're not the
Ass Crack Bandit.
Shh! Keep it down, huh?
I made a deal with the dean.
He said as long
as I confessed,
he'd let me slide
on the meth stuff,
and then he'd buy me
a space heater for my stable.
Yeah, but why call
the dean and pretend that...
I didn't call no dean.
I don't call nobody
don't call me.
I got to go backstage once
and meet the whole band,
everyone, except Dave.
There's a whole
album of photos
online if you go to...
You actually wouldn't
be able to access it.
I use an older,
British form of Facebook
called "Mug-scroll."
(THUNDER)
(MUSIC CONTINUES
IN BACKGROUND)
I guess I should be going.
No, no, stay.
We're just getting to
know each other.
I really shouldn't,
I have a...
Oopsie.
Aren't you going to
pick those up?
Yes.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Just reach down
with your hand and...
Bye!
(DISTORTED)
This is the Ass Crack Bandit.
I find it funny that you ever
thought you could catch me.
Jeff.
It's Duncan.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Annie?
Jeff?
Very nice.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, bloody hell,
my shoe is untied
by British standards.
(GRUNTS)
Here we go.
One bunny, two bunnies.
Oh! Get Britta!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
JEFF: Annie!
Did Duncan get cracked?
ANNIE: Where's the bandit?
Do you see him?
JEFF: Over there!
ANNIE: Come on, let's get him!
Shirley,
what are you doing?
Looking for you.
Did you see someone
come this way?
Jeff, Annie,
Pierce is dead.
MAN: (OVER RADIO)
Tonight's celebration was
cut short by some tragic news.
Pierce Hawthorne,
14-year Greendale student,
entrepreneur,
and expert heart attack faker
has passed away,
for real this time.
Pierce had been
recently banned from campus,
but not from our hearts.
He's survived by many ex-wives
and all of us here
at Greendale
that called him friend.
If you're listening, Pierce,
you were
a hell of a D&amp;D player.
It's time to level up.
Up next on the dial
is Dr. Farts.
(PARTY HORN TOOTS)
I can't believe
Pierce is gone.
Yeah.
Life is weird.
It's a container
for all this little stuff,
and you get caught up in it.
And then,
the container just...
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
That hallway
led to a dead end.
We might've had him.
I should get home.
Haven't slept.
The case goes cold again.
Don't worry.
I got a feeling he'll be back.
Or her.
(SOULFUL MUSIC)
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ 25 cents at a time
he's taking our souls
♪ Government men can't help,
we're all alone
♪ Are you feeling
the breeze?
♪ Did you pull
your belt tight?
♪ You know that it's wrong,
you know that it's right
♪ Out of the shadows
down the coin goes
♪ Why, oh, why
do you suppose?
♪ Only the bandit knows
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh
♪ Oh, whoa, oh, oh, oh
♪ A-S-S C-R-A-C-K Bandit
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh
♪ Oh, whoa, oh, oh, oh
♪ A-S-S C-R-A-C-K
can't stand it ♪
STAR-BURNS:  You know,
climate change is
threatening our world,
but there is a solution.
The cat car,
the world's first
animal-powered vehicle.
My original prototype
was hunger-based.
But sometimes,
cats aren't hungry.
My new model will use
a rear-fixed dog system.
But dogs cost money,
your money.
By donating to this project,
you'll be like an investor,
except without taking
all my profits.
Donate $5,
and you get a thank-you email.
$50 gets you a T-shirt.
$100 gets you a T-shirt
and a thank-you email.
(CAT MEOWS)
All aboard the cat car,
and all aboard helping
our nation's global warming.
MAN:  Did you get any of that?