Well, that was
a weird afternoon.
I guess I knew Pierce
was part of a weird,
futuristic cult,
but I wasn't prepared
for a funeral
with so much beeping.
Well, let's not judge.
Everyone has a right
to whatever fake religion
they delusionally choose.
Abed, you were by the coffin
for a long time.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Although...
♪ Troy and Abed
are in mourning ♪
Will you guys
please stop doing that?
I can't believe you did it
during your eulogy.
So uncomfortable.
I don't think the audience
got that we were singing
"mourning" with a "U."
You were singing
"mourning" with a "U"?
Oh, no.
I still don't fully understand
the Laser Lotus theology.
So Pierce's body
is in the coffin,
and we buried it,
but this energon pod
contains his life...
Vapor?
Yeah, it's all right here
in this incredibly persuasive
literature they passed out.
Once you reach level 16,
you can see
the color blurble.
Of all the ridiculous
cartoon nonsense.
If there is a blurble,
the Lord keeps it hidden
for a reason.
What up, n-bombs?
How was the funeral?
Awesome?
No, Chang, our friend's
funeral was not awesome.
It was deeply sad.
You know, funeral style.
Excuse me.
I thought you
guys hated Pierce.
(ALL PROTESTING)
We did not hate Pierce.
Craziness.
All right, are you sure
you guys aren't
just doing the
"respect the dead"
jig-a-lig?
I think you have us mistaken
for you, Chang.
I don't know.
I definitely remember you
complaining about him
a lot.
We complained about him
when he was alive.
This is different.
Can't believe we'll never
see him again.
Just a reminder
you gotta live
life to the fullest.
By the time
Pierce was my age,
he had already been fired
from 15 jobs.
I've only seen two
Police Academies.
The last two.
Well, he's gone too soon
but won't be soon forgotten.
I would say you're
quite correct, Mr. Winger.
Who the hell are you?
My name is Mr. Stone.
That's easy for you to say.
And for us to say.
I work for Mr. Hawthorne.
He specified in his will
that no matter
how natural in appearance
the circumstances
of his death,
a private inquest should be
conducted to determine
whether any one of you,
his former study group,
murdered him.
(GASPS)
What?
To be cleared,
you must all submit
to a polygraph test.
Aw, schnizzle.
You guys are in trouble!
Later.
Mr. Chang, I presume.
You're also listed
as a suspect
and requested to participate.
Fine, but I ask
the questions.
I'm afraid
I can't allow that.
All right,
then just the "fine" part.
(AIR HISSING)
Oh! Oh!
We're losing Pierce!
Everyone, quickly!
(SUCKS IN AIR)
Oh!
(STRAINED)
Someone get a balloon.
♪ Give me some rope
♪ Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
♪ To run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up
♪ Tied up,
dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one,
they all just fade away ♪
I always wanted
to try a polygraph.
They're like the pie fight
of cop movies.
Or the acupuncture
of the legal system.
I can't believe Pierce
would think
we might murder him.
Yeah, what a waste
of murder.
I mean, he was, like, 79.
I don't suppose anyone
wants to know
I consider
this a violation.
Mmm-mmm.
Come on, it's just Pierce
being Pierce.
It's his final wish.
If I had a final wish,
I'd use it to stay alive.
Let's do it.
How do we begin?
We're to start
with Miss Perry.
State your name.
Britta Perry.
Have you ever had
any thoughts of violence
towards Pierce Hawthorne?
No.
Lie.
I mean, I may have wanted
to slap him now and again,
but I didn't kill him.
In all your sexual fantasies
about Pierce Hawthorne,
none of them involved
his murder?
What? No.
But you have had
sexual fantasies
about Mr. Hawthorne.
No! What kind of
question is that?
I'm asking the questions
just as Mr. Hawthorne
wrote them down,
I assure you.
Mr. Winger,
state your name.
Jeffrey Winger.
Are you gay?
No.
Are you sure you're not gay?
Yes.
Gay murderer says what.
What?
He's telling the truth.
I've been instructed
to point out
that that means you're gay.
Ms. Bennett.
Hmm?
State your name.
Shirley Bennett.
Are you a dishonest person?
No.
She thinks that's true.
Uh, you could have
just said no.
I'm watching you
acting scientific
and then adding
your little two cents
every now and again.
Huh?
Continue.
Is it true that you're
a platinum level donor
with the pro-life organization
prenatalpatriots.org?
What?
Keep it cool, girls.
It's my money.
It's my choice.
Yeah, well, if I wanted
the government in my uterus,
I'd fill it with oil
and Hispanic voters.
Keep it frosty, ladies.
Don't let your goats
get gotched.
Mr. Barnes, state your name.
Troy Barnes.
D'oh! I meant to say,
"Butts Carlton."
He did mean to say,
(SNICKERS)
She said it.
Mr. Barnes, did you get angry
when Mr. Hawthorne told you
Fat Albert died of diabetes?
Yes, like any American would.
Angry enough to murder him?
No.
Is it true that you
and Abed Nadir
have an elaborate
doomsday escape plan
to be used in the event
of zombie attacks?
We may have a designated
rendezvous point
and a couple of bugout bags
filled with gold coins
and condoms
just in case we need to
bargain our way onto a boat.
The gold coins
are for buying food.
Does your doomsday plan
account for the welfare
of any of your other friends?
Pass.
Answer the question.
No.
Troy! Rude!
It's a doomsday plan,
not a picnic plan.
Do you really wanna see
the horrors
we might have to endure
just to get on a boat?
I guess not.
That's a lie.
Ah!
He's doing it again.
Pierce is doing it again.
Mr. Chang, state your name.
Benjamin Franklin Chang,
ready to deal out the truth.
Nothing to hide.
Let's do this.
Have you ever masturbated
in the study room?
Mr. Nadir, state your name.
Abed Nadir.
Have you ever 9/11'd anyone?
Nope.
When you were a child,
did you ever kill a squirrel
with a slingshot
and were surprised
that you felt nothing
and wondered if
you were capable of
doing it to a human?
No.
(SIGHS)
Ooh.
Do you and Troy still actively
use Jeff's Netflix account
without his permission?
Wait, what?
You told Pierce that?
You logged in at our place
and never logged out,
so we use it.
Is that why my review
of  The Grey
is constantly changing?
Yes, stop giving it
four stars.
I like Liam Neeson!
Then send him a message about
the roles he chooses.
Look, this is not the issue!
You're stealing from me!
And as your roommate,
you're making me
an accomplice.
I had no idea.
Lie.
Why would I even try that?
State your name please, Miss.
Annie Edison.
Miss Edison, did you use
your exceptional intelligence
and organizational skills
to plot the foolproof murder
of Pierce Hawthorne?
Aww!
And no.
Is it true that you
overcharged Troy and Abed
for their share of the rent?
(WHISPERS)
Pierce!
Annie?
Yes, but for a good reason.
You guys know you're bad
with money.
I padded your share
of the rent by $10
and I've been putting it into
a savings account
that yields 4%.
You'll be thanking me
in six years
when you find out
you have $86.
That's jacket money.
Oh, did you hear that, Abed?
We've been washing
paper plates and
making our own toothpaste.
But don't you worry.
When we have robot bodies
on the moon,
we can share a free jacket.
Annie, you should know better
than to horde money.
That's a stereotype.
Was that anti-Semitism?
No!
That's sensitivity.
It's anti-Semitic
to do things like that
when you know full well
you're Jewish.
Whoa.
We could have bought a tire
for our tire swing
with that money.
Or your own Netflix account?
Liam Neeson? Not that great.
Your rating system is flawed.
(OVERLAPPING SHOUTING)
All right!
(SHOUTING STOPS)
Let's begin.
Wait, wait.
What do you mean, "begin"?
That completes the calibration
round of questioning.
We're ready to begin
the formal inquest.
I think we're ready to end.
We've humored this
long enough.
Jeff, it's for Pierce.
Look, respect for the dead
is only a thing
because the dead usually
don't do any more damage.
Ah.
That's true.
You can quit any time
you like.
But it should be noted
that Mr. Hawthorne's estate
is worth over $20 million
and only those cleared
of his murder
can receive
their bequeathments.
I'm only gonna say this once.
Clearly, Pierce is trying
to lure us
into a labyrinth
of emotional manipulation
and strategic instigation.
And I think we're all
smart enough to know
we should quit
while we're not ahead.
I do believe we should...
Yes, definitely.
...quit while we're ahead.
Absolutely.
Right.
They're all lying.
We all know that,
you judgmental bitch!
Miss Perry, have you ever
eaten at the sandwich shop
started by Mrs. Bennett
and Mr. Hawthorne?
Yes.
And what sandwich
would you order from
Shirley's Sandwiches?
The only one I can,
the Helen of Soy with no mayo.
Helen of Soy.
Are you aware that in order
to save money,
Shirley stopped
using real tofu
and replaced it with
a midwestern tofu substitute
called "Meatfu"?
Oh, my God!
Oh!
It's still not
actually meat...
legally.
You have never respected
anything that I hold sacred!
I'm sorry!
Shirley, did you know
that Britta was high
on marijuana at
your son's baptism?
I'm sorry?
Well, no higher than usual.
Not true.
You did drugs in my church?
No, I did drugs in
the parking lot of
your church.
How else do you
expect somebody
to sit through something
like that?
At least with a bris there's
an element of suspense.
Well, next time, I'll have
Cheech and Chong
do the warm-up!
Guys, these questions
are obviously designed
to turn us against each other.
If we want to beat Pierce
at his game,
we have to own up to
our mistakes and
forgive each other.
Mr. Winger, is it true
that you keep trophies
of your sexual conquests?
(ALL GASP)
In a church, Britta?
For shame.
It's where Jesus
gets his mail.
Answer the question,
Adrien Grody!
I know what Pierce
is referring to.
I have a box of
forgotten items in
my apartment.
I happen to be a single male.
Visitors leave things.
Is one of your trophies
a pair of
Miss Perry's panties?
(GASPS)
You told me
a hawk stole them!
You exploited me
and made me believe
in a slightly
more magical world.
If you want to collect
women's underwear,
can't you just buy them?
They have to be
won in battle.
Oh!
Blegh! Gross!
Jeffrey!
Awesome.
I think we can all agree
that the gross thing here
is that Pierce is snooping
through my stuff.
Not really, Abed and I
go through
your stuff all the time.
Why do you keep bread
in the freezer?
And why does your bathroom
mirror say, "You're special,"
when you fog it up?
Look, I don't have
to answer these...
You took a shower?
Yeah.
Mr. Barnes.
Okay! I did it!
Okay?
I killed Pierce!
Lie.
Okay, good.
Just making sure.
You and Abed Nadir
have a specialized,
exclusive handshake
that you refuse to do
with your other friends?
Absolutely.
Mr. Barnes, did you invent
that handshake?
Yes.
Lie.
MR. STONE: Mr. Barnes,
are you a subscriber
to the video blog
"Fun for Friends"?
No.
Lie.
Silence, wench!
(OVER PHONE)
Hi, I'm Kevin,
this is Kyle,
and here's
a fun handshake
you can do
with your best friend.
All right!
Thanks for watching, guys.
Don't forget to rate us,
comment, and subscribe.
Can't look at you right now.
Then you should know
I'm crying.
I forgive you,
but only to escape
the established pattern
of self-righteous
indignation
followed by immediate
comeuppance.
Mr. Nadir.
Okay, I guess it's
happening anyway.
You broke my heart.
Continue.
Is it true that you planted
geo-trafficking devices
on everyone in the group
so that you would know
where they are at all times?
Yes.
Okay, you guys are changing
your faces.
Are you mad at me or hungry?
You're tracking us?
We're mad at you, Abed.
Why?
Because we already live
in a totalitarian
surveillance state.
Do you not read
my status updates?
But I'm not the government.
I'm your friend.
That's what governments
say, nimrod.
It's cool.
When one of you
gets kidnapped,
you'll be glad
you don't have to count
the bumps on the highway
from the trunk of the car.
Are those blinking dots us?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, what's this one
all the way to the side?
That's where Pierce is buried.
Is that why you were spending
so much time by the coffin?
I was trying to get it back.
They're expensive.
And he's not moving anymore.
Abed, where did you plant
these things?
If you makes you feel
any better, you'll
never find them.
I know you know it's wrong
to do that without telling us.
Shame on you!
Okay, I'm ashamed.
BOTH: Lie.
Miss Edison, is it true
you once secretly dosed
the members of
your study group
with a pharmaceutical
amphetamine?
Uh-hmm.
Oh, uh, yes, kind of.
What?
It sounds worse on paper
than it was.
We were cramming
for the Anthro final.
Everyone was falling asleep.
I put five milligrams
of something-something
in your coffees
and we all got an "A."
Done!
I'm a bad person
for tracking your location,
but you altered
my brain chemistry?
I was up for three days
that week.
I invented an entire language,
you  fliztbarping gitzgorg.
I'm sorry.
You messed with my brain.
That's a big deal.
This is a big deal.
I don't mess
with your brain, Annie.
You kind of do.
I don't think I do.
What about
her Facebook boyfriend?
What?
That's different.
You made a profile
for a fake dude
and lured her
into an online relationship.
He's catfishing you.
You're Olympic pole-vaulting
hopeful Brent Underjaw?
I noticed whenever you were
in a relationship,
you hummed a lot and made
pancakes in the morning.
It wasn't about hurting you.
I did what I did in the name
of breakfast.
I bore my soul to you!
I told you about my holding
hands at Disneyland fantasy.
Do you care about people
at all, Abed?
Answer on the polygraph!
Jeff made me apply
for handicapped parking
so he can get a better spot.
Britta's the one
that invited Garrett
to Annie's birthday party!
Troy won't sit
on a toilet seat after Jeff!
When we're alone,
Shirley refers to you guys
as "those people."
Oh! When Annie's
with other females, dude,
she calls Jeff her uncle!
Shirley thinks
we're all going to hell!
You are all going to hell!
Oh, what?
(OVERLAPPING SHOUTING)
Guys, stop!
We have to stop letting
Pierce do this to us!
Mr. Hawthorne hasn't asked
a question in quite
some time, Mr. Winger.
He's right.
I actually forgot for a second
that Pierce was dead.
Maybe that's what he wanted.
Or maybe he wanted us
to know we're no better off
without him.
Or no better than him.
Hmm.
He kind of nailed it,
didn't he?
I didn't just masturbate
in the study room.
I masturbated everywhere.
Everywhere!
Huh.
Confession is good
for the soul.
You should try it sometime.
There's another round
of questions,
if you'd like to continue.
You want to give us a moment
to sit in our own filth
before you heap
another bucket on us?
It's strange
after all these years
how much we've kept hidden
from each other.
You'd think by now
we would have learned
to be better people.
I think we got into this mess
by thinking
there was such a thing
as better people.
Wait.
That's it.
If we're no better
than Pierce,
and Pierce is no worse
than us, then that means
nobody's really that bad.
So what if we're willing
to suffer
and inflict pain at the mere
prospect of material reward?
If we stop now,
that doesn't make us better.
It just makes us so dishonest
that we would rather be poor
than admit we're flawed.
Pierce admitted he was flawed,
and he died rich.
Let's celebrate his life
and death in the honest way,
not by saying fake nice things
around a casket,
but by admitting
we're monsters
and clawing joyfully
for some of his cash.
So does anybody
have anything left
before we continue?
Let's empty our tanks of
lies once and for all.
I'm Jeff Winger,
and if I had my choice,
I would rather look
at myself naked
than the women I sleep with.
I'm the one who hit
Jeff's Lexus
in the parking lot.
It wasn't a taco truck,
and it was racist of me
to improvise
such an ethnically
specific vehicle.
I only give money
to homeless people
when I'm walking with someone.
I've never been
to LEGOLAND.
I just wanted you guys
to think I was cool.
I can be passive-aggressive
sometimes.
Don't everybody disagree
at once.
Oh, Lord, I did it again.
When any of you chew gum,
I want to punch you.
You may as well
have submachine guns
in your mouths.
It vibrates my skull.
Everybody clear?
All right.
(ALL AGREEING)
Mr. Stone, hit us
with your grand finale.
May it be as brutal
as we deserve.
Very well.
Mr. Hawthorne's final round
of questions.
Britta Perry.
"Do you know that you hate
yourself more than you should
"and that your passion
inspired me?"
No.
That's true.
She didn't know.
"To Miss Perry,
I leave my iPod Nano
"filled with music
to take life
less seriously by."
Oh, that's nice.
"I also leave you
this liquid nitrogen
cooled cylinder
"of my hyper-virile sperm
"in case your lesbian
lifestyle one day wears out
"and you wish to raise
an army of geniuses."
Shirley.
Hmm?
"Did you know that you
are not only a credit
"to your race and gender,
but to our species,
"and that I was intimidated
by your strength of character
"and business acumen?"
Yes.
"To Shirley Bennett
"I leave my spacious
timeshare in Florida..."
Oh!
"...where she can take
what's-his-name
"and however many children
she has now."
Uh-huh.
"I also leave you a cylinder
of my sperm."
Oh.
Annie Edison.
"Did you know that you were
always my favorite?"
You mentioned it once,
but...
"I leave you this tiara, which
you once refused to accept.
"It's the same tiara
I used to wear
"when my mother
would verbally assault me
"for not being a little girl.
"Also sperm."
Jeff Winger.
"Did you know you're gay?"
No.
"Agree to disagree.
"To you, I leave this bottle
of fine scotch
"so that you're less tempted
to drink this cylinder
"of even finer sperm."
Abed Nadir. "Did you know
that you are insane
"and nothing that you said
ever made any sense to me?"
Yep.
Here's your sperm.
Troy Barnes. "Did you know
that you possess
"the greatest gift life
can give.
"The heart of a hero.
And that it's up to you
"not to waste it like I did?"
I think.
"To Troy,
I leave the obligatory sperm."
Maybe it's because
everyone else got one,
and because
it's an old man's semen,
but, um,
I'm kind of disappointed.
"In addition, I am prepared
to leave Troy Barnes
"my remaining shares
in the Hawthorne
Wipes company,
"currently valued
at $14.3 million."
(GASPS)
"On one condition.
"You must first sail my boat,
the  Childish Tycoon,
"by yourself
around the entire world."
What?
Again with the bait
and switch.
"When I was 23,
my father asked me
"to do the same thing to earn
my adulthood and his fortune.
"Of course I cheated
and floated off
the coast of Belize
"for a year doing coke
with John Denver.
"I always regretted it.
"I'd like to give you a chance
to do what I never did,
"become your own man."
Okay, I'm a lawyer, Troy.
It should be possible
to contest these conditions
as unreasonable...
I'll do it.
And Pierce can take
his mind games
and his sperm
and he can put...
I'll do it.
What?
Troy?
Pierce was
a crazy old coot, yeah,
but I think he knew
something about me
that even I didn't know
until now.
Because he's offering me
something
I've been searching for
my whole life.
Millions of dollars.
And being a man
or whatever he said.
Jeff, say something.
I'm speechless.
Somebody say something!
Abed?
Cool.
Cool, cool, cool.
That's a lie.
And then that sperm
came down!
I mean,
I couldn't say anything!
But oh, my God!
I was gonna explode!
And then that one,
that last question,
with all of that nice stuff
out on the table,
and you guys were
having this discussion
about whether or not to quit?
At first, I was like,
"Aaaaah!"
But you did it!
You did it!
It was amazing!
You're amazing, man!
You're amazing!
Guys, this is the best.
We should do this every week.
Oh, I'm a fun guy, you know?
I mean, you talk about lying.
I was lying the whole time.
This is who I really am.
This is me.
This is the real me.
I'm artistic.
Ideas come to me all the time.
I have this idea for a movie.
It's about this guy
who oversees polygraph tests,
and the biggest obstacle
is how good-looking he is.
People can't focus
and tell the truth.
It's unbelievable.
By the way, uh,
we never found out
how Pierce died.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe
I didn't tell you yet.
It was dehydration
from filling up
all of those cylinders.
I mean, it's how I want to go,
but, hey, I'm a little nutty.
Mmm!
Are you guys thinking
what I'm thinking?
Shots!