This is from
all of us, Troy.
When you're sailing
around the world,
you'll be going
through a lot of countries,
so we got you
a universal translator.
(GIGGLES)
Cool.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Bueno.
Bueno?
Cool.
Thanks, guys.
I didn't know
going-away parties
could be so much fun.
I should leave all the time.
Let's not forget
it's okay to be sad too.
Britta, do you get kickbacks
from big buzzkill?
I'm serious.
We know.
The truth is, a member
of our family is leaving.
For a year, maybe more.
Psychology has taught me
the human mind has
a tendency to rechannel
separation anxiety
in the form of frivolity
and giddiness, and...
I don't want us
to waste our chance
to acknowledge how much
we're gonna miss you.
PELTON OVER PA:
Attention, Greendale.
Oh, announcements!
Announcements!
(LAUGHS)
Oh, I love these.
SHIRLEY: Whoo!
Announcements!
I'm standing here
with Abed Nadir,
who has chosen to give
his best friend, Troy,
the very special
going-away present
of declaring
a school-wide game
of Hot Lava!
Cool!
Ooh, that sounds like fun!
What? No!
Process your feelings.
PELTON:  Hot lava is
the sweet, classic
children's game
in which you are not allowed
to touch the floor,
or you're dead.
I think it's cute,
and while I normally
don't condone
climbing on furniture,
Troy and Abed's friendship
has been such
a special and magical part
of Greendale,
we owe it to ourselves
to honor it.
Abed, anything to add?
Yes, take this seriously.
Stay on furniture.
No books, no bags.
The dead can't talk.
No coming back
as a lava monster.
Ooh!
Yes!
(LAUGHS)
Hot lava!
Come on, guys,
this is classic avoidance.
I have to go talk to him.
ABED OVER PA:
Oh, and because
the non-awesome
often need incentive
to do awesome stuff,
the final survivor will win
my near-mint condition
number one issue
of  Space Clone,
valued by the Comics Authority
at $50,000.
(STUTTERS) I'm sorry?
The floor turns
to lava in 10...
(ALL SHOUTING)
Nine, eight, seven...
Did you say 15 or 50,000?
Six...
Oh, who am I kidding?
Help, lava!
ABED:  Five, four,
three, two...
(ALL SHOUTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
BRITTA:
Professor Duncan?
You stay back, Britta!
I'm not afraid
to push a girl
into make-believe lava.
In fact, it's been
my primary strategy.
I'm staying in the game,
so I can talk to Abed.
I'm worried about him.
What I'm worried
about is money.
My self-published novels
aren't going to publish
themselves.
Don't regress
to primal behavior
just because it's allowed.
We're human beings,
not the editors of
Teen Vogue.
They're setting
a terrible example for
today's young women.
Well, I'm sorry, Britta,
but it's either you or me...
And I'm me.
No!
Yes, yes, yes!
Oh! (GROANS)
Real nice, Winger.
This is why the English
never win any sports.
'Cause everyone else cheats!
Britta, there you are.
Sweet, sweet, portable chairs.
Plastic gold.
Four-legged diamonds.
You claiming this?
Lava joust?
Did you all hit your heads
on each other's heads?
ANNIE:
Let's get real, Britta.
Once the last of
the chairs are gone,
a sofa hopper like you
won't last 20 minutes.
You want to
join this alliance,
or you want to
join the lava?
Fine.
But I'm not learning
the new names for anything.
(GRUNTING)
Centipeding isn't
the fastest form of travel,
but if we find more chairs,
we can do the inchworm,
scootenanny,
the reverse Danny Thomas.
Do you think this game's
gotten a little out of hand?
Eh, feels normal enough
for a school
that's on 911's
blocked caller list.
And I like that Abed
wanted to send
Troy off in a cool way.
Send him off
or put off sending him?
I think this imaginary lava
might symbolize
Abed's fear of change.
I think that diagnosis
symbolizes
your lack of a psych degree.
(SCOFFS)
Mama mahogany,
feast your feet
on that stack of sticks.
(SIGHS)
Eh, too easy.
Could be a trap.
As if someone else
is taking this game
as seriously as you.
Let's keep
this centipede rolling.
Give me a chair.
Ugh, so stupid.
Come on.
Shh, shh!
ALL: Locker,
locker, locker.
Locker, locker.
Locker boys!
Oh!
(ALL GROWLING)
Locker!
Winger, Edison, and Perry.
What a delicious combination.
ALL: (CHANTING) Lock, lock!
What are we getting
from this extra level
of commitment?
We're getting your chairs,
your food,
and the names of your
same-sex celebrity crushes.
Everyone has one, don't lie.
Then you're free to go...
Into lava!
ALL: (CHANTING) Lock, lock.
ABED AND TROY:
Ooh-whoo-ooh!
Stand down
or meet your doom, Chang.
You're in no position
to make threats,
floor strider.
Our truce ended when
you banished us
from the pay phone bench.
You used that bench
to upset the balance.
By the vapors of Magmarath,
we will restore it.
You have gods?
Locker boys!
Earn your M&amp;M'S!
Locker!
Troy and Abed
intimidation stance.
(ALL WHIMPERING)
I guess that actually looked
the way it did in my head.
(METAL SCREECHING)
(STEAM HISSING)
(LAUGHING MANICALLY)
Hiya, kids.
I'm criminology professor
Buzz Hickey,
and this...
This is just a little
something I threw together.
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
Aah!
(GRUNTS)
(SLOW MOTION)
Jump!
Aah!
(LAUGHING)
Centipede, centipede!
Okay!
(ALL SCREAMING)
CHANG: Pull harder!
Pull harder! Pull harder!
(BOTH SHOUT)
My same-sex celebrity crush
is Nathan Fillion!
(SHRIEKS)
Nathan Fillion!
Jeff, Annie!
Get to Shirley Island.
We'll meet you there.
Abed, save yourself!
Abed, before Troy
"dies in lava,"
you can save yourself
emotionally
by honestly experiencing
the pain of him leaving
Greendale!
We can do this
in three steps.
Britta, jump to
that trash can.
Troy, start inchworming.
BRITTA:
What's the third step?
The third step's survival.
Good luck, Britta.
Seriously?
Troy!
TROY: Sorry, Britta,
Abed knows best.
But I'll always remember you
as kind of slowing us down
and complaining a lot.
Oh, my... No!
(LAUGHING)
(VEHICLE STOPS)
They abandoned you?
This game's doing
bad things to people.
Now me, I'm just in it
for the money.
My son's getting gay married.
The flowers alone,
you have no idea.
I get it.
I lived in New York.
(SIGHS)
All right, Miss Perry,
climb aboard.
It's fake killing time.
(CHUCKLES)
Welcome to Shirley Island.
No furniture
beyond this point.
Leave your weapons
at the door
and any spare doors
at the entrance.
(CHAIN SQUEAKING)
(BANGING ON POT)
Then came the now-now times...
When the floors
were covered...
ALL: Ah.
...with the burny touch.
ALL: Ooh.
You made it.
Friends!
Welcome to Shirley Island,
where all your dreams
come true,
if you dream of standing
on a table and
pissing in a jar.
Where's Britta?
She didn't make it.
Oh, that's too bad.
ANNIE: Poor Britta.
ABED: It's okay.
Her sacrifice got us this far,
and now we can't lose.
Why not?
Because now we're
on Shirley Island,
and according to legend,
so is the orb.
I'm sure I have no idea
what you're speaking of.
This is a place of peace.
And profit.
Come again?
You're not really
playing, Shirley.
You're a merchant,
and more power to you.
But don't withhold
power from others
just to make money.
We want the orb.
Abed.
Listen, I'm still a little
raw from what happened
with Britta back there.
I mean, fun is fun, but I
don't want my last day here
to be a day
where everyone hates me.
Last day?
HICKEY OVER PA:
Citizens of Shirley Island!
(STEAM HISSING)
What have you brought
to my door?
Stay back!
(ALL GRUNTING)
SHIRLEY: My God,
it's Hickey.
Aah!
And he's got chair walkers!
(ALL CHANTING)
(FEEDBACK)
Come out with your feet
on the floor,
and there will be no need
for nudging or jostling.
I did not skip my son's
birthday for second place!
(PLUNGERS POP OFF FLOOR)
I want to say something
to you guys about
mental health.
Is that Britta?
Is she alive?
Why did you think
she was dead?
We, kind of, left her.
Left her for dead?
Sounds bad
when you put it that way.
Can you put it
a way that sounds good?
You do realize this isn't
just a pile of chairs, right?
This is a crib,
and you're curled up
inside there,
sucking your thumb,
because you're too scared
to say good-bye.
Well, it's time to grow up.
The adults are here,
and we're gonna
tear down your fort.
Chair walkers, attack!
(HOWLS)
(ALL HOWLING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
My name was Vicki!
Tell my story!
These are my only pants!
I can't get them dirty!
(BRITISH ACCENT)
I'm actually British!
Leonard!
Butter 'em up!
You got it!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Cirque du so long,
you high-stepping
acro-bastards!
Do you have
any rolling chairs?
Behind the curtain.
Abandon fort!
Women and man-children first!
Hey, seat feet!
Chair to dance?
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
ANNIE: Ah!
(GRUNTS)
ANNIE: Aah!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Yes!
(LAUGHS)
Aah!
Britta, I'm your friend.
I can't hear
dead people, Annie.
I'm in a world
of imagination.
Ha! Then imagine
what the floor looks like.
I don't have to.
I'll just imagine where
you're about to be!
That's the same as
imagining the floor.
Then you just admitted
that's where you'll be.
Knock, knock, Britta.
I'm not gonna say
"Who's there?"
Because someone
on the floor is knocking.
Well, that's lame.
You have to say,
"Who's there?"
Floor!
What?
That's who's there!
Yeah! But it's for you!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Aah!
(RUMBLING)
Shirley, give us the orb,
and we can save
Shirley Island.
The orb can't save
Shirley Island
because Shirley Island
is the orb.
In a cool way
like Keyser Soze
or a lame way
like  Jewel of the Nile?
You tell Buzz Hickey
that Shirley Bennett said...
Well, I don't want
to waste your time.
Just think of something cool
and give me credit.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
But the door I'm knocking
on is your home,
so if I'm the floor,
it means you're dead.
If you're the floor,
you're already dead.
Just do it right!
Knock, knock!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Oh!
Who's there, bitch?
Floor!
Aah!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(STEAM HISSES)
BOTH:
♪ Troy and Abed in a bubble ♪
Ha! Hickey,
you chicken.
(AIR HISSING)
He gutted us.
Retreat!
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING) Hello?
Hello?
I'm the only one left.
I won 50,000 bucks.
That's 50,000 lottery tickets!
(LAUGHS)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTING)
You can't outrun
your emotions!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTS)
Aah! I had a dream
like this, but it was sexual.
I will force you two
to grieve properly
even if it kills us all!
Go away, Britta!
Oh! Aah!
(SHOUTING)
ABED: Yay!
TROY: Ow!
ABED: Yay! Ow!
Sorry about
our butts touching.
(METALLIC CLANKING)
Okay, we'll go into the vents.
They'll never find us there.
I say we take a stand here.
I mean, someone's got
to win sometime.
Not if we never
kill each other.
Then we can play forever.
Right. Wait.
Abed, the floor can't
be lava forever.
The game's got to end.
It's not a game
for me, Troy.
I'm seeing real lava
because you're leaving.
It's embarrassing,
and I don't want to be crazy,
but I am crazy, so...
I made a game that
made you and everyone
else see what I see.
(LAVA BUBBLING)
I don't want it to be
there either, I swear.
I want you to be
able to leave,
but I don't think
the lava goes away
until you stop leaving.
So the only way I can help you
is by giving up my chance
to be one person?
(DOOR BURSTS OPEN)
(BOTH SHOUTING)
You guys ready for closure?
Of your caskets?
Guys, stop, okay?
The lava's real to Abed.
TROY: It's not a game to him.
Oh, no.
You know what I think?
I think he's used
to getting his own way.
I think he's never met me.
Aah!
No!
(METAL CRASHING)
Abed! Abed.
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
Unbelievable.
When this game is over,
I'm gonna shove you back.
Abed, give me
your other hand!
It's down to us.
You or Britta will be
the winner.
I'm not leaving, okay?
Just... I promise.
(STUTTERS )The floor's
not lava now.
Just give me your hand.
I don't think the lava's here
because you're leaving.
I think it's here
because I won't let go.
Sorry.
Bye.
Abed.
Abed. Abed!
Abed!
Abed! Abed!
(SOLEMN MUSIC)
Abed.
TROY: He's fake dead.
Forever.
(DING)
(TRANSLATES TO SPANISH)
Shut up.
What?
(TRANSLATES TO SPANISH)
Stop!
He's not really dead.
No, but he's really
playing dead,
and he's not gonna stop.
Here.
Congratulations, you win.
You don't get it.
No one gets Abed.
I got him a little.
This is my fault.
I don't deserve to fake live.
Wait! No.
I can fix him.
How?
(SIGHS)
I don't know.
In real life, I don't know,
but I can fake fix him.
Uh, I can clone him.
I'll clone him.
Go on.
I just need
his DNA.
Let's get his DNA.
Don't touch the lava.
You might be
onto something.
I'm gonna find
discarded technology
from this once great
civilization and start
a cloning machine.
Mm! Okay,
I'm placing this cellular
regeneration sequencer
on the spot
where he died.
Here, don't forget this.
This is a laser guidance
system that keeps the
regeneration sequence from
um, jib-jabbing.
Jib-jabbing?
BRITTA: Initiate
regeneration sequence.
(BOTH IMITATING
BEEPING AND WHIRRING)
(LAUGHS)
It worked.
We made a perfect
clone of Abed.
(NECK CRACKS)
Actually, Britta's
work was sloppy.
I'm not an exact replication.
I have all of Abed's
abilities and memories,
but I'm missing
his wild emotionality.
Although I think I may be
able to let Troy go now.
I don't know.
I haven't been
completely honest.
I'm really scared
to go on my trip.
Well, you don't have to go.
Your clone can.
Right.
So you guys are
all cloned up too, huh?
Yeah, believe in cloning.
Yeah.
(HORN HONKS)
Well, guess that's my ride.
I'm so excited for you.
You're gonna see the world
and experience new cultures.
I mean, technically
all culture has
been homogenized
by 50 years of
American imperialism,
but at least
the candy bar wrappers will...
(SIGHS) God, there I go.
Almost Britta'd
our good-bye, huh?
I'm the worst.
You're the best,
and I love you.
(WHISPERING)
I'm better at sex
than Jeff, right?
I've yet to have
anyone worse.
All I ever wanted in
high school was for
Troy Barnes to notice me,
and then I ended up
living with you.
I'm pretty lucky.
I'm not. I had a chance to be
your friend in high school,
but I was too busy
trying to be cool.
I missed out on four more
years of Annie.
Aw!
You are the coolest
guy I know.
I hope I make you proud.
I've never stepped foot
outside of Colorado.
You're becoming much cooler
than me by doing this.
(MOUTHS)
Thanks for looking
out for me.
Thank you for putting up
with the boring, old mom
in your college study group.
You made a furniture fortress.
You're the badass
from our study group.
Clone Troy.
Clone Abed.
By the way, when I cloned you,
I had to patch some missing
parts of your DNA
with genes from
a homing pigeon.
You may notice side effects,
like a compulsion
to come back.
Cool. Clone hug?
JEFF: So, you're really just
gonna pilot this thing
all on your own?
Well, Pierce's will stated
that someone would be
assigned to travel with me
to verify that I don't cheat.
BURTON: Captain Barnes.
We should probably set sail
while the wind is still in
our favor, don't you think?
Engage.
(COME SAIL AWAY PLAYING)
♪ A gathering of angels
♪ Appeared above my head
Now, Troy, I know
it's gonna be difficult
for you to interact with me...
No, no. That was
the original Troy.
I'm his clone.
Let's get
the lead out, Burton.
Aye, aye, sir.
(ENGINE STARTS)
♪ They said, come sail away,
come sail away
♪ Come sail away
with me, that's...
♪ Come sail away,
come sail away ♪
♪ Come sail away with me ♪
BURTON: You know,
starting a sea voyage
from landlocked Colorado may
not have been the best idea.
We'll drive to the river
and then take
the river to the ocean.
Actually, I never thought
I'd see you again.
I have a couple
Star Trek questions,
if you don't mind.
No, go ahead.
What time did you guys have
to get up in the morning?
Does every writer
write for one character?
What's a best boy?
I saw it in the credits once.
Why don't they
call it Planet Trek?
You never go to a star.
Not one episode.