It's settled.
The urinals
in the women's restroom
will be turned into planters.
Onto chores.
We need some able bodies
to clear out a space
in the east hall's
storage room.
I'll do it.
Really?
Yeah, Annie always
goes from the easy chores
to the hardest.
That's true, isn't it?
I'll do it too.
Yeah, me too.
Okay, that concludes
this meeting.
Oh!
Aw, man!
Nobody picks up
on my patterns!
What am I
gonna say next?
Graham cracker!
You didn't know.
Hey, it's the "Aw couple."
ALL: Aw.
Look what Rachel got me.
Pile of Bullets.
An interactive old west themed
VCR game from the '90s.
RACHEL:
I found it at goodwill.
It was between a thighmaster
and a Dick Tracy
burger king glass.
RACHEL: Happy anniversary.
Anniversary?
I guess I should learn
your name, young lady.
Oh, Rachel.
Rachel.
Nice to meet you, Rachel.
You can go.
Okay.
WOMEN: Aw!
Anniversary?
Yeah, Rachel and I
have been dating
for one of your months,
but our relationship
is 12 times more efficient,
so it's really been a year.
Our sleep cycles
are in synch,
we can communicate
with our eyebrows,
and she knows
my Netflix password,
Jeff's Netflix password.
Damn it.
I'm changing that.
I changed it.
To what?
Nice try.
Annie, can Rachel
come to our place
to play this tonight?
I can't afford
to take her anywhere.
Well, my brother's in town
for the week,
and I'm broke too,
so I was gonna make him
dinner tonight.
Cool.
Double date?
Dinner and 1993
interactive VCR game?
What are you making?
Salmon.
(GRUMBLES)
Buttered noodles.
Buttered noodles
are my favorite.
Hmm.
Ah!
Quick announcement
for two of Greendale's finest.
Payday is postponed
until next week.
So this...
(RAP MUSIC PLAYS)
Is my freestyle rap apology.
♪ Well, I'm
a peanut bar
♪ And I'm here to say
♪ Your checks will arrive
on another day
♪ Another day, another dime,
another rhyme,
another dollar
♪ Another stuffed shirt
with another white collar
♪ Criminals, wall street,
taking the pie
♪ And all the black man
gets is a plate
of white lies
♪ Prisons! Recruitin' 'em!
Police be shootin' them
♪ Rap artists lootin' them,
labels all dilutin' them
♪ Barack Obama
is scared of me
♪ 'cause I don't
swallow knowledge
♪ And I spit it for free
♪ Let me clear my throat,
ah ha, ah ha ♪
(FEEDBACK HUMS)
(SOBBING) I don't know
what that was, I don't.
I don't know what that was.
(HYPERVENTILATING)
♪ Give me some rope
tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
So nice
to have the Edison kids
under one roof again.
Remember when we used to
cut carrots for mom?
(MONOTONE)
Yes.
I need a soda.
Oh, okay.
One, two, three.
Door's busted.
Landlord's in jail
and money's tight.
Yeah.
(DOOR CLANKS)
(RATCHETING TWIST)
Oh, my God!
Anthony!
Thank you!
Yeah.
Hey, Abed, a quick word.
Hmm.
What would you think
about my brother
moving in with us?
Do I just
keep cutting carrots?
Yes, Anthony!
He has money.
He's handy.
You're putting me
on the spot.
I guess my kneejerk concern
would be that he's a Viking
and might only use our home
as a temporary base
before moving inland
where lumber
is more plentiful.
He's a good guy.
We can't afford to keep
splitting the rent two ways.
You have a better idea?
How about Rachel?
Is that a joke?
Is it cool if I poop?
No, Anthony!
Just cut the carrots!
You've been dating Rachel
for a month.
I don't think
you heard his question.
The answer is yes!
Rachel and I have been dating
for the equivalent of a year.
Oh, really? 'Cause I feel like
I've been hearing about that
for two years.
You can't just microwave
a relationship
like it's a bean burrito.
Annie.
I ain't living with your
month long girlfriend, brah.
Well, I ain't living
with your wack ass,
don't-know-whether- to-keep-
cutting-carrots-
or-ask-if-he-can-take-
a-poop-brother.
Can we discuss this later?
Rachel's on her way,
and I'd like to
practice my smile.
I guess it was just air.
Why are we organizing
a storage room?
JEFF: How is this
not a janitor's job?
Can I ask you something?
Why the hell do you have
all those muscles
if you're gonna bitch
about moving boxes?
Is the air working in here?
I'm sweating like a catholic
on judgment day.
(GIGGLES)
Just a little
protestant humor.
I've got more.
Oh, can't wait.
Nothin'.
Wait, there's something
in there blocking the vent.
SHIRLEY: You gonna open it?
You do realize nothing good
has ever been found
in a vent, right?
It's a vent.
JEFF: Whoa.
Huh.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
(SWITCHBLADE CLICKS)
Oh!
Intro to Chemistry.
Third edition.
(WHISTLES IN AWE)
Mint.
$200 retail.
160 on the street.
Why are there books
in an air duct?
Why is there hot sauce
in the bathroom?
It's Greendale.
They must be stolen.
We have to tell the dean.
JEFF: Hold on.
Let's just calm down
and have a slow,
pleasant chat
about possibilities.
What kind?
All kinds.
Anything is possible.
We might one day
have hover cars.
Kale might be poisonous.
And we might not have
to get the dean involved here.
Jeffrey, these are stolen!
From who?
By who?
How long ago?
It's "from whom,"
"by whom."
But he nailed
the third question.
Look, we are the committee
that deals with
Greendale's problems.
Now did you see
anything on our list
about a pile of missing books
that are worth more than
the school they're hidden in?
JEFF: One thing's for sure.
If we hand these over,
they'll really go missing.
And you think
that money's gonna be used
to cut our paychecks
or to make another
rapping peanut costume?
I can't believe
what I'm hearing.
Fine.
You wanna go to heaven?
Walk away, more for us.
I'm an accomplice now!
If I walk away,
I'll only get into heaven
by turning you in.
But what
about your restaurant?
What about your kids?
Ms. Bennett,
when god talks to you,
what language does he use?
Because in my experience,
when he thinks
you deserve something,
he drops it on you
like a ton of bricks.
Okay.
All right.
But if we're gonna do this,
we're gonna do this
clean and safe.
We're gonna move these
to my restaurant
in bread carts,
and we're gonna sit on 'em
until we know they're cold.
Then we're gonna price them
through a third party,
and we're gonna unload them
in a single score.
None of
that nickel and dime crap.
I don't wanna leave a trail.
BOTH: Yeah, great.
Wonderful.
Okay, let's count
these babies up.
Yeah, great.
ANNIE: When we were kids,
Anthony and I would play
time machine.
We would go,
"Oh, no!
We're in barbarian times!"
Quick!
Back to the time machine!"
And then we would run
back to the time machine.
It's true.
I bet that's why Abed
is like a brother to me.
You guys are so alike.
I can't accept that based
on one time machine story.
Rachel, did you tell Annie
about your waterpik?
I suppose now is
as good a time as any.
I own a waterpik.
ABED: Annie has one too.
You guys both care
for your teeth
the same amount.
If you shared a bathroom,
it'd go pretty smoothly.
Anthony said
he could fix our cabinets.
Rachel used to mop floors
when she worked at Kmart.
She mops good.
Is this a real conversation
or are we being bugged
by the feds?
Abed.
Sidebar.
What do you think happens
after you die?
I don't know.
You're lucky.
Stop trying to
sell me on Rachel.
Stop pitching Anthony
so hard.
You're like ice cream cake
out there. Overkill.
We need a roommate.
We're broke.
I vote for Rachel.
I vote for Anthony.
Flip a coin?
No. Coins create
parallel timelines.
Rock, paper, scissors?
That's a nine sided coin.
ABED:
What about  Pile of Bullets?
ANNIE: You wanna decide
on a roommate
with a 1993 old west themed
VCR game?
If Rachel or I win,
Rachel moves in.
If you or Anthony win,
I'll politely surrender
and count down the days
until he eats me.
All right, it's settled.
Is this working?
It's a handshake
in progress.
Who wants to play
Pile of Bullets?
Not me.
You have to.
Oh, it's okay,
we don't have to.
It's not okay.
We do have to.
We all have to,
and one day
we'll tell you why.
But for now, let's simply
retire to the TV area.
For the highest stakes
1993 interactive VCR game
of your entire
young adult lives.
BRITTA: Okay, let's see
what you got.
(SNIFFS INTENSELY)
Yeah.
Okay.
I know somebody
that knows people.
I can get you
a price per book,
find a buyer,
and make a deal.
For half.
That's ridiculous.
I'm assuming
more than half the risk.
Half is fair.
Not really.
Because they're ours,
all 100% of them.
Giving you half is not fair,
it's silly.
Okay, good luck.
You wanna re-blindfold me?
I know we're in E9
in the east wing.
I know that
because it smells like weed.
Not my weed.
Look, I'm willing
to give her half.
Hear that, Britta?
You can have half
of Jeff's share.
That's not what I meant.
That's what you're offering
by giving her
half of the total.
Either she can get half
of all of our money
or she can get half
of your share.
Either way, you walk away
with about 16%.
That's not fair.
SHIRLEY: Damn right.
Here's what is
25% for each of us.
Take it or leave it, Britta.
CHANG:  ♪ Legalize it
♪ Don't chang I... ♪
Hey, guys.
Hey.
Look, if something sketchy
is happening,
I don't care.
So I'm just gonna back
out of the room now and...
He can't leave.
(SCREAMS)
No! No!
I didn't see anything.
I did not see anything!
Britta, find some rope.
I've got rope.
"Each player starts
with six bullet tokens,
"ten gold certificates,
and a color-coded
posse token."
There's two types of tokens?
I'm sure
we'll figure it out.
(HARMONICA MUSIC
PLAYS OVER TV)
MAN: (OVER TV)
Howdy!
You look like a real group
of gunslingers.
Everyone in town's
mighty scared,
what with all the gold
and the outlaws.
But only one of us
can make it out alive.
Are we robbing the town?
By now, you should have
your bullets, your gold,
and two wild west tokens each.
Hang onto those tokens
no matter what.
There's two kinds
of tokens.
Two each?
Now when you hear
the word "Draw,"
or when you see
a square with a color
or number matching
one of you
or your opponent's cards,
the first one of you
to say, "Bang,"
wins
the challenged player's token
and the amount
of their bid in gold!
What's going on?
BOTH: Shh!
Ready?
Yes?
I'm not.
Shh!
(SILENCE)
Are we supposed
to be bidding?
Draw!
I bid!
Pow! Bang!
(MALE VOICE OVER TV)
Rattler!
Bang! Five!
Bang?
Yee-haw!
Bang bang! Five!
Bang?
Not bad!
Collect your tokens and let's
get on to the next round!
What are you doing?
Stop that.
He said,
"Collect your tokens."
He can't see you.
Didn't Abed
shoot whoever's five?
Draw!
ALL: Bang! Bang! Bang! Bang!
Odd numbered players,
give up two cards!
Draw!
We have numbers?
(MONOTONE)
Bang, bang,
bang, bang, bang, bang.
ABED: Okay, okay,
I don't think
we're doing this right.
Are we sure this is a game
and not some art film?
Now what do we do?
We rewind it
and start over.
Okay, I'll allow it.
No, it's okay.
We gave it our best shot, no?
(SCOFFS)
I'm sorry, Rachel,
is this your home?
Oh, God, no, I'm sorry.
Well, this is
what we're playing.
But it doesn't
make any sense.
Oh! It sounds like
Anthony wants to forfeit.
He doesn't.
Don't forfeit, Anthony.
Rachel, we can do this.
(WHISPERING)
Just focus, okay?
Okay...
Okay.
(HARMONICA MUSIC
PLAYS OVER TV)
Howdy!
BOTH: (FLAT)
Howdy.
I love textbooks.
That's why I stole these.
All right, knock it off.
What?
You gotta make it
sound believable
or you're not getting
outta here.
(WHINING) I'm trying.
Try harder!
Go.
(SOBS)
I love textbooks.
That's why I stole them.
Mmm.
Look at this one.
(SMOOCHES)
(SIGHS)
Stolen textbooks
are the best kind.
I stole all these books
and put 'em in this room
so I could come kiss them.
That's all, thank you.
(SOBBING)
Please, I'm on parole!
Exactly.
So keep your mouth shut
or we'll send this file
to everybody.
What do you mean
"Everybody"?
(AS GARY OLDMAN)
Everybody!
(CHUCKLES)
Look, I can't
do this anymore.
What?
I'm out.
It's too far, it's too...
Evil.
Look, you guys
can split the money.
I'm just gonna leave quietly.
Goodbye.
(GRUNTING)
JEFF: What the hell?
HICKEY: Yeah?
What the hell? Ow!
I can't let you leave until
we're done with this deal.
Shirley, this is not what god
wants you to be doing today!
We had our chance
to think about that.
He dropped this on us
like a ton of bricks.
Right, Hickey?
Oh, yeah, definitely.
Not to say that this
isn't getting insane.
(JEFF GRUNTS)
MAN: (OVER TV)  Black hat Bill
sure ain't the forgivin' type.
You! Green player!
Yes, partner?
You can do better than that,
can't you?
Yes, pardner!
Pick another player that you
want to draw a cactus card.
I choose Anthony!
Anthony, draw a card.
Oh! This is a good one.
Keep this for when
you're in a quick draw.
Rachel, your turn!
What do I do?
You roll, you roll.
Here.
There. My turn.
Stop! Snake bite!
Lose a turn.
Anti-venom.
I'll take two.
Draw!
BOTH: Bang!
ABED: Okay,
I bid five bullets.
I raise six.
Eleven.
Pass. Reverse!
Hold it!
BOTH: Yee-haw!
Did you remember
to say "Yee-haw"?
Anyone that didn't
loses a turn.
Collect your coins!
Anthony, I'll trade you
two snakes for a bullet.
Just say yes!
I don't wanna die.
Stop her, Rachel,
stop her!
Bang?
No! Bid Five!
Tornado!
BOTH: Tornado!
Nine tornado!
Pass! Seven!
Reverse!
Two tornado!
Pass!
Double!
Draw!
BOTH: Bang!
(GUNSHOT)
ABED: Oh, come on.
You son of a bitch!
Come on.
(MUMBLING)
Come on, come on.
(BLOWS)
(GROWLING)
Come on!
(BEEPING OVER TV)
(HARMONICA MUSIC PLAYS)
MAN: (OVER TV)
If one of you
rolled your bullet number,
you're the winner!
(GROANS)
Fast-forward to the red screen
to get your gold.
Well, more food
for the buzzards.
Looks like modern times...
Have come after all.
See ya in the city.
I wanna go home.
Me too.
No, we have to play again.
Abed, I think
you're having one of
your special times, okay?
So I'm gonna give you
some space.
I don't want space.
I want you to move in here.
What?
But that's not resolved!
Anthony might
move in, so...
What?
We want one of you
to live with us.
Yeah, we're settling it
with a game of
Pile of Bullets.
That is not an explanation
that should make anybody
want to live here.
Abed, I don't like
this side of you,
and I do not like that side
of VCR technology.
I am glad that
it's a dead medium.
That was very uncomfortable.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
I don't really know
how girlfriends work,
but I don't think
you have one anymore.
Okay, cool.
See you there.
I'm meeting my guy in an hour.
He wants to see a sample,
set a price,
and then we'll do
the exchange.
JEFF: (CHUCKLING)
Oh, brother.
So Britta doesn't know
how much she's getting
from this guy
that none of us
will ever see again.
But she knows one thing
for sure
she'll be right back with it
so you can divvy it up,
even steven.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, man, that is rich.
What's supposed to stop her
from robbing you guys blind?
CHANG: What are you gonna do,
call the cops?
I'll go with her.
Oh, yeah. Good plan.
Yeah, leave Hickey here,
and the two of you
do the deal.
Yeah, what the hell?
When did I volunteer
for Guantanamo duty
while you two traipse off
to the Cuban equivalent
of Las Vegas?
Havana, right?
Guys, don't listen to Jeff.
He's just trying to divide us.
Says the woman who's willing
to take care of the cash
by herself.
As if you're
Mr. Trustworthy.
Why do you have
so much access to rope?
Hey, you're the one
who left the door unlocked
so Chang could get in here.
How do I know
you didn't do that on purpose?
BRITTA: Guys. Guys!
Calm down.
I'm sure we can work this out.
We just need to stay cool
and talk it through.
I'm sorry.
That didn't work out
the way I planned.
I'm sorry.
But you didn't leave me
any choice.
You were acting very poorly,
I didn't know
if I could trust you anymore!
You dragged me into this.
I didn't want this.
Huh?
You're packing?
Yeah.
You're leaving?
Because of last night?
Yeah.
I just think there's
some unresolved issues here.
You're right.
I'm still really hurt
by mom turning her back on me
when I went to rehab.
And I guess part of me
was mad at you
for siding with her,
so I thought you
moving in here was
some kind of...
Moral victory.
What? No.
I mean unresolved issues
involving the black guy
in all these photographs.
ANNIE: Troy?
Hey, I don't know
his name, man.
I just know he's clearly
left some kind of vacuum.
And screw you.
What did I have to do
with mom?
I was 13.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey.
Hi.
I'm here
to do my third act apology.
Abed, I don't think...
Wait.
Don't reject it
until the whole thing's
been served up.
Dobry.
Open your locker please.
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKS ON LOCKER)
Hey.
I wanna tell you something.
Abed, this is adorable.
Just because it's adorable
doesn't mean
it's not important.
Listen.
I've been accelerating
our relationship
because I've been worried
I wouldn't pass
a lot of the tests.
I wanted you to move in
because I thought
if Annie was around,
I'd have less chance
of screwing things up.
You're not
screwing things up, though.
That's good to know.
But the problem with me
will always be
that I can
never know for sure.
There's not a huge amount
of people in my life
that haven't
eventually kicked me out,
and I don't always
see it coming.
I don't want it to happen
with you.
Well, don't manipulate me
and don't keep secrets from me
and we'll probably be okay.
Cool.
(GASPS)
It stopped raining.
Yeah, it sure did.
(SQUEAKING)
Aw, you hired
a stunt person.
No, I did not.
Where'd you get these?
They were an inheritance
from my father.
He was a collector.
Mmm-hmm.
How many?
120.
Well, for the whole bunch,
maybe 20.
Thousand?
Dollars.
$20,000?
Twenty non thousand dollars.
20 regular dollars.
You might get that
from a recycling place.
These are misprints, honey.
Check out page 105.
Well, I can't because
there's no page numbers.
Ah! Well, that would be
a problem.
MAN: You know,
"Class, turn to page
there is no page...
"Oh, well,
if there's no page number,
you can't turn to it."
I've better things
to do with my life.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
Although we
haven't been saying it,
Troy was an important part
of our apartment.
He kept the peace.
Yeah.
Goin' a little crazy
without him.
Maybe we need to live
with a therapist.
Or at least someone
crazier than us.
(FOOTFALL)
Let's give Craigslist
another try.
I think Craigslist
is the way to go.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Yeah.
ANNIE: Are you guys
all wearing the same clothes
from yesterday?
We've been through some stuff.
But we learned something.
HICKEY: No, we didn't.
We learned that sometimes
there's no lesson.
How is that learning?
We played  Pile of bullets.
Can we just get
this meeting over with?
ANNIE:
So how'd the cleanup go?
ABED: I learned how to smile.
Don't step,
don't step to me.
I like coffee and water,
Uh, damn it!
I lost it.
I lost it!
Okay.
I will get back to you.
Thanks.
Who was that, sweetie?
Guess they want me
for that Wild West videotape
board game thing.
Pile of bullets?
Yeah.
(PLATE SHATTERS)
Devin, you pick up
that phone right now
and you call these people
and you tell 'em
you want this part.
These VCR games
is where everything is headed.
Can't you see that?
You just became
the Luke Skywalker
of the new  Star Wars.
We've gotta move.
We do?
Oh, yes, indeedy.
We have got to move
to Los Angeles.
But I work here.
Oh, please.
You call
Apple Computers work?
What kind of company
offers stock options
as a Christmas bonus?
That ship is sinkin'.
Sweetie, remember
when we were talkin'
about trying cocaine?
Yeah...
I think we should start
looking for some right now.
Because we're gonna
be able to afford it.
Okay.
I mean, if you're sure.
I've never been more sure
about anything
in my entire life.
Pile of Bullets.
(BOTH LAUGH)
WOMAN: Oh, yes!
Did you get any of that?