Something for the committee
to put on their radar,
insurance.
What about it?
School needs some.
I can ask around
on the street.
What the hell?
Oh, too cool
for street insurance?
Must be nice.
My sister wants to know
what I'm bringing to my
grandson's birthday party.
I'm sensing
an emergency
collage situation.
No, I wasn't invited.
My son had a kid
three years ago.
I barely get to see him
on major holidays.
I mean, who in the hell
does he think he is?
You saw your son
at his wedding.
No, that's Furio.
That's my gay son.
Him I get.
Hank's a knob.
He doesn't have
any hobbies or interests.
All he does is play that...
What do you call that crap
with the dungeons
and the dragons?
Dungeons &amp; Dragons?
That's the crap.
SHIRLEY: Ooh.
I know that game.
We play Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
Mmm-hmm.
Guys, let's play D&amp;D
to help Hickey reconnect
with his son!
Huh?
Was everyone's
takeaway from last time
that we can use D&amp;D
to reprogram brains?
Nobody feels that
we almost caused a suicide?
We prevented one.
Fa...bulous Neil
felt like a nobody,
and thanks to us,
he's still out there,
doing this and that
in the background.
A satisfying sequel
is difficult to pull off.
Many geniuses have
defeated themselves
through hubris,
making this a chance
to prove that I'm better
than all of them, I'm in.
All in favor of a game
of Dungeons &amp; Dragons
to reunite Hickey
and his son tomorrow night?
ALL: Aye!
(HICKEY GROANS)
Well, okay.
(CHUCKLES)
It's short notice,
but, uh, I think
it'll be good for me.
(EPIC MUSIC PLAYS)
So, Dad,
I'm just curious.
Um, what is it
about Dungeons &amp; Dragons
that suddenly leapt
out at you at age 60?
Um...dungeons.
It'd be the dungeons.
ABED: Let's begin.
A blood-orange sunrise
crests the peaks
of rage mountain,
as the eight of you
arrive at the troubled realm
of Galindor.
Ahead to the north,
a bridged ravine.
Beyond that,
a mysterious black tower
where, rumor has it,
an evil necromancer dwells.
Your goal,
reach to the top
of the tower
and destroy the necromancer,
freeing the realm
from his evil magic.
Oh, that's just
what I love about
role-playing games,
is being told
exactly what to do.
Me too.
You should introduce
yourselves.
I am...
Oh, boy!
Joseph Gordon Diehard.
Really. (CHUCKLES)
Son of Sir Riggs Diehard.
Well, I'm Sir Riggs Diehard,
so I guess I'm your dad
in the game too.
Oh, my God, so cool.
SHIRLEY: Oh, it's nice.
CHANG: Isn't that weird?
Oh, boy.
Guys, I don't suppose
that this is some sort
of contrived
paint-by-numbers adventure
that's designed
to force an emotional bond
between me
and my emotionally
stunted father, is it?
BRITTA: No way, Jose.
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
I got an idea.
Why don't we just
sort of reshuffle these...
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
And just
redistribute them...
No, I don't...
And just mix
'em up a bit.
JEFF: Is this right, Abed?
Should we...
And here we go.
Hello, everyone.
I am Tristram Steelheart.
I'm a holy cleric
with a mace
and a dumb name.
Ouch.
I'm Tiny Nuggins,
a, uh, a thief,
and the rest is gibberish.
Greetings,
I am Fibrosis the ranger.
I'm crouton,
the half-orc druid.
Druid? Oh, crouton.
Hector the well-endowed?
Again?
You think that's
a weird coincidence?
I'm a troll named
Dingleberry.
That's my mom's
nickname for me.
Well, I'm who hickey was,
Sir Riggs Diehard.
I am Joseph Gordon,
son of Riggs.
I protect the blade
of diehard,
a family sword
whose power
knows no equal.
In our clan,
the leader carries the hilt,
his eldest heir,
the blade,
for we believe
man's greatest weapon
against evil
is the bond between...
(CHOKES UP)
Is the bond
between a father and son.
ANNIE: WOMAN: Aw.
What would you guys
like to do?
We should cross
the bridge
and head for
the black tower.
Huzzah? Huzzah?
Huzzah.
Yeah, I don't know
if I'm gonna head
across the bridge, actually.
I mean,
what else is out there?
What's south
or east or west?
How about it, Aziz?
If I walk too far south,
do I fall off your
graph paper there?
You can head south.
I've generated some details
about the surrounding area.
You know,
for God's sakes, Hank,
it's been five seconds.
Can you not do this?
Hey, you tell me.
Are we losing?
No. It's not
a competition.
The only winner
is fun.
Mmm-hmm.
ANNIE: We're having fun!
I go to Tristram,
and I'm laughing,
and I pick him up,
and I carry him
to the bridge.
It's fun!
Hector the well-endowed
is trying to lift you.
I cast
Torvin's flesh of fire.
(FIRE WHOOSHES)
Tristram murmurs
an incantation.
His body becomes wreathed
in white-hot flame,
burning Hector for...
Six damage.
Hey!
Well, Hector,
that's called
self-defense.
Tristram's
flesh of fire spell
has caught the bridge
on fire.
The rope supports
in the middle snap,
causing the bridge
to twist.
I'm rolling dexterity checks
to see if you all hold on.
Oh!
Abed, considering
the bigger picture,
you think
it might be possible
you miscalculated
the strength
of the bridge, hmm?
Good point.
It would've been
constructed
in the third age
by goblins,
and they used
primitive iron anchors.
The ropes are yanked
from the rocky slopes
on both sides,
and you all plummet
into the ravine below.
ANNIE: Abed!
(ALL PROTESTING)
Oh!
Abed!
You plunge into
the icy, raging waters
of Skull river.
(GASPS)
Ow!
You know,
what's your problem?
What's your problem?
You didn't invite me
to Sebastian's birthday.
(LAUGHING) I knew it!
Who hoards
a man's grandson?
He's not your grandson.
He's my son.
And I didn't invite you
to the birthday party
'cause I wanted
to enjoy it.
You know,
fathers and sons,
there is a lot of power
between them.
Yeah.
Stop it.
And I spent
a long time
letting that power
push me away
from my dad,
and I regret it.
So what's ever
between you guys
will only get fixed
when you're together.
They're not together.
Abed, you're not helping.
I'd be a pretty bad
dungeon master if I was.
Jeff, Hickey, Annie,
and Shirley,
you've been washed
down the left fork
of the Skull river,
the others to the right.
(WATER SLOSHES)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING) Father!
ABED: If you're
going to continue,
I need Hank, Britta,
Chang, and Dean Pelton
to go into a different room.
Yeah, we're not
going to continue.
Thank you very much, guys.
This was just awesome.
Yeah, wait, wait, wait.
I'll play your dragon game
with you.
But let's
make it interesting.
If I kill the necrophile
before you do,
I come
to my grandson's birthday.
We'll settle it like men.
Or whatever you call
the guys that play this.
Okay.
But if I kill
the necromancer
before you do,
then you don't
go to Christmas
or Thanksgiving
at Aunt Rachel's.
You don't even go to that.
Yeah, but I will
if you don't.
Okay, fine.
HANK: Okay.
Let the real game begin.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
I will find you!
Well, I'm assuming
you guys can help me
beat him,
because if we lose,
I'm gonna punch each
of you in the heart.
ABED: You awaken
on a muddy riverbank,
surrounded by treacherous,
god-forsaken,
non-zipline
vacation jungle.
I build a fire
and construct
a crude wooden rack
to dry my boots
and oversized codpiece.
All right, and I can
make some s'mores
out of horse meat
and s'more horse meat.
Build a fire?
Horse s'mores? Screw this.
The river runs east.
I head west.
Tiny Nuggins scampers
into the jungle.
Hey, pal,
I didn't scamper
in the jungles
of Nicaragua,
and I'm not gonna do it now.
Wait, come back!
I follow him.
Me too.
Tiny Nuggins, if we rest,
we'll regain our strength.
And lose my family.
I'll imaginary sleep
when I'm imaginary dead.
Through the brush
in the distance,
you notice a patrol
of half a dozen hobgoblins.
(HOBGOBLIN GROWLS)
Hobgoblins?
Larger, stronger, and
worth more in scrabble
than regular goblins.
Everybody, get down.
I punch him in the heart.
What?
Well, I punch him
in the heart,
and I keep running.
There are no women
with them, are there?
I got class.
You charge toward them,
alerting them
to your presence,
and you attack
the nearest one
in the chest.
You miss and fall down.
What?
Oh.
The hobgoblins
are heading toward
Nuggins with spears.
Oh, no!
Uh, I cast entangle
on them.
Crouton the druid
waves her arms,
causing grass, vines,
and branches
to entangle
the limbs of...
(HOBGOBLINS GROAN)
Four hobgoblins.
(SQUEALS)
The two free hobgoblins
fire arrows at Crouton.
One pierces her shoulder.
(ARROW THWACKS)
Oh!
ABED: The other her chest.
Ow!
I fire an arrow at them.
(ARROW WHOOSHES)
Hit.
Ah, these hobgoblins
don't like their odds.
They bolt into the jungle.
Yes.
Yeah, you better run.
Go find a name
that's not just
another creature's name
plus "hob."
ABED: Uh-oh.
Crouton?
I'm here.
She was badly wounded
from her fall
in the Skull river,
and the arrows
were just too much.
I'm sorry.
That's it?
Is she dead?
Yes, that's it, hickey.
I'm dead.
But it's okay.
I'm on your side.
Which is why I'm dead.
And I may be gone,
but just remember
whenever the wind whispers
through the woods,
you got me killed.
Now, you listen to me,
young man.
I've punched about
a thousand hearts
in my life.
I never, never missed.
Have you ever been
a three-foot-tall halfling
running through
two-foot-high vines,
trying to punch
a seven-foot monster?
I'm gonna go check
on the others.
You might want
to check your character.
Or just kind of
generally take
this game seriously.
Your son does.
I take a moment
of silence
to mourn my fallen comrade,
Crouton...
Before rifling
through her belongings.
(HUMMING)
What news of my father?
You have no way of knowing
where the others are.
Damn it.
You're still
traveling north
along the narrow
cliff edges of
the Hawthorne mountains.
Okay, I'll roll
for any encounters.
I'd like to cast
a healing spell
on Fibrosis.
Oh. Thank you.
But I... I'm not gonna
help you kick your dad
out of your life.
I don't think
this competition
is healthy,
and I don't think
what you did back there
was cool.
Look, you think
I'm the bad guy
because I didn't invite him
to my son's birthday.
But you know
where he was
for most of my birthdays?
Little place that rhymes
with "not there."
Times Square?
The four of you
hear an ominous screeching.
Moving upward into view,
three huge, white arachnids
with eagle wings.
Sky spiders.
I draw my sword
and I cry out...
(SWORD UNSHEATHES)
"Back, eight-legged demons!
"I will not scoop you up
with a catalog
"and let you outside
on this day!"
Stay your blade,
Joseph Gordon.
Sky spiders are
as frightened of us
as we are of them.
Plus they eat
all the sky mosquitoes.
Mmm.
I cast speak with monsters,
and I say,
"Hello.
You're looking well."
The lead spider
bends four knees
and twitches
its hairy ovipositor,
rhythmically secreting
and retracting
a giant droplet
or drop of silk.
Oh.
Fibrosis, as a ranger,
you recognize this
as the arachnid's signal
of submission.
Oh. Nice work, Tristram.
Damn, you made
that sky spider
your bitch, yo!
You've tracked
the hobgoblins
to this shack.
One guard
hob-guards the door.
That's what they
call guarding.
Go.
Sniper arrow on the guard.
It strikes true.
The guard drops.
I move to the doorway.
Detect traps.
None detected.
I enter.
Left flank.
Right!
One hobgoblin, facing east.
Backstab.
Double damage.
Critical hit.
He's dead.
Footsteps behind
the door to the north.
I notch two arrows.
I climb the walls
to get above the door.
Five goblins enter
from the north.
I fire.
Both arrows hit.
Cleave!
You kill one
and wound another.
I drop on the last one
and grapple.
You got ahold of him.
This one is for crouton.
With his dying breath,
he utters...
(CREEPY VOICE)
"The dark lord
will kill you all."
Wait, these things can talk?
I want two taken alive.
I want to try something.
Hi. I'm Tiny Nuggins.
I'm gonna put
my dagger down
right here,
so we can just talk.
(GRUNTS) Human trash.
Yeah, look,
I'm gonna give it to
you straight.
We're looking
for a necromancer.
We don't need
two goblins to find him.
So between
you and your friend,
who do you think's
the most useful?
(GRUNTS)
Man, your friend
sure can talk.
Liar. He'll never turn.
Oh, yeah,
because of that
famous goblin loyalty.
I could never drive
a wedge between you
and some guy from work.
Uh, I was best man
at that guy's wedding.
Oh?
Your friend says
you just got married.
Congratulations.
Too bad about the food.
I hope your
flesh rots in...
Wait.
What about the food?
Oh, I guess he didn't
like your wedding toast.
Golbak said that?
Klang doesn't approve
of you and Lisa, Golbak,
and I don't get the sense
it's because of his
feelings for you.
You know,
I think about Lisa,
sitting in that hole
in darktooth canyon
with little Framrok
and Griknog
rolling about
on the wolf pelts.
Come on,
between you and me,
which one do you
think is yours?
No!
(CHUCKLES)
I know where the tower is.
(SINGING)
The sky spiders
have flown you
as far as their complex
religion allows.
They set you down and express
through intricate prancing
directions to the tower.
Yes.
Father, forgive me.
I have traveled
so far from you.
How many game days
since the skull river
ripped us apart?
How many real hours
since I've gone pee?
We seek this necromancer.
Why?
Our reasons are dreams,
our dreams, dust.
I send word
on wings of sparrows,
in hopes they might find you.
Abed says the odds
are near impossible.
That's enough for me.
Should you receive
this message,
I know of a way
to reunite.
According to
my character sheet,
if I rub the blade
of our magic family sword
while you rub the hilt,
twin beacons of light
will reveal our locations
to each other.
Each night,
I will think of you and rub,
praying for the night fate
will find us
rubbing together.
Your son,
Joseph Gordon Diehard.
Something strange
has happened.
A sparrow lands
on Riggs Diehard's shoulder.
(BIRD TWEETING)
It carries a note.
Abed, I...
Rub my sword's hilt?
A beam of light shoots out
from your location,
as the hilt of diehard
seeks its blade.
The beam arcs
and meets an equal beam
in the woods to the north.
Is that where
the others are?
Yes, 10 miles away,
same as you.
So we'll be arriving
at the tower...
At the same time
tomorrow morning.
This began as a race.
But it may end in war.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Does anybody
have a toothpick?
I got a piece of popcorn
stuck in my tooth.
You know, it's, like,
right under the gum,
and, you know,
I've been trying, like,
for 15 minutes
with, you know, my tooth
and, like, with my tongue
and with my finger,
and I'm always one tooth off,
and I just can't seem to...
Oh, hello, there we go.
Anyway.
But it may end in war.
(WHISPERING)
Maybe after all
we've been through,
we should just call
this thing off.
What, you think
that's up to us?
You've seen the way
he talks to me.
He doesn't want
his own father in his life.
He'll do anything to win,
and that includes
attacking you.
And you best believe
that your little friends
in there are drinking up
his kool-aid.
This is a man who
thinks of grandchildren
like trophies.
(SPITS)
Which is why
he'll play to win.
And why I can't let him.
(INHALES)
(GASPS)
Rise, brave,
sweet dingleberry.
Rise.
Both parties have
arrived at the black tower.
Hi, guys.
Father.
Joseph Gordon.
(SIGHS)
Mmm-mmm.
We are here,
so Tristram Steelheart,
lord of the sky spiders,
can slay the necromancer.
You guys cool,
or are we gonna
have to get red?
Tiny Nuggins,
waterboarder of goblins,
will do the slaying,
because every man
has the right
to hang out
with his grandson.
Too bad you're outnumbered.
No, they're not.
I'm not part of this.
I'm Joseph Gordon Diehard,
and I am only here
to hug my father,
which I now do.
It's a trick.
I'm not letting
him hug me.
I hug my father.
He has gunpowder
in his pants.
I draw my sword.
Stay back!
I draw an arrow.
So do I.
Troll sound!
Jeff, do you lower your sword?
No!
Dean, are you...
I hug my father!
You're impaled.
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Oh!
(SPLATTERING)
(GASPS)
(HAWK CRIES)
(WHISPERS) Worth it.
Ugh. Good lord.
Son slayer!
I attack Jeff!
Arrow at Chang!
Arrow at Annie!
I head for the door
of the tower.
So do I!
Taste the blade
of Diehard!
I run for cover.
I turn a snake into a rope.
Fire two arrows at Annie.
Spear, spear.
I take the kid. I pop him.
Three damage.
Lightning bolt,
lightning bolt,
lightning bolt.
Cure moderate wounds!
I spray all over them.
I hold Britta's face
in a puddle.
Seven damage.
Cleave, cleave, cleave!
I fire two arrows.
(OVERLAPPING SHOUTING)
Dingleberry smash!
Plus three,
demonic eye look.
And shove it up them!
After that, I put one
right behind the ear.
(OVERLAPPING SHOUTING)
(GRUNTS)
Sir Riggs,
hand in your character sheet.
(GASPS)
(CLANGING)
(SCREAMS)
Top floor of the tower,
one door.
I open it.
I cast flame
strike on him.
You cast that already.
Mace.
Okay. Missed.
Ah.
I hit him
with a throwing dagger.
You used all your knives.
Ah, what... Will one of you
guys take care...
What? You're all dead?
I keep going.
I follow.
You've reached
the necromancer's workshop.
You see his bed,
some bottles of goop,
some other
necromancing crap,
but no necromancer.
I search.
Can I search,
or are you gonna
stab me in the back?
Hey, I am a thief,
not a wuss.
I search, too.
Mmm-hmm.
You find a secret door.
It's easy because
it's already open.
It leads to a ladder,
which goes straight down
to another open door
on the back of the tower.
Ah, man.
Way to go.
That's great.
He just got away.
Hey, you can't just
say he's gone.
You owe us an ending.
I owe you nothing.
I am a dungeon master.
I create
a boundless world,
and I bind it by rules.
Too heavy for a bridge?
It breaks.
Get hit?
Take damage.
Spend an hour
outside someone's front door,
fighting over who
gets to kill him?
He leaves through the back.
He's out there somewhere.
You might find him,
if you get your
crap together.
Hey, guys.
Take it from
a bunch of ghosts.
This is no kind of life.
You need fresh air
and frozen yogurt.
It's on me.
(ALL GASPS)
Hug it out.
Oh, see...
Hug it out?
Gag me.
Who even uses that phrase?
All right, I'm climbing down
the ladder. I'm gonna
find this guy.
I stay and search
the workshop.
Does he have any stuff
there that can heal me?
You do find some potions.
Okay, well,
I get half of that.
Excuse me, you just
went down the ladder.
Well, I can hear you...
Can I hear him
looting upstairs?
Not if I move about
silently.
Fine. Fine.
If I heal you,
can we divide the potions?
Okay. But I decide
who gets what.
All right, fine, but
we've gotta be
wary of traps.
I don't have to do a damn
thing that you tell me to do.
What's going on?
Shh.
You outta your mind?
Do you wanna get...
Oh, you give me a break.
The necromancer or not?
Do you want...
(ARGUMENT CONTINUES
IN BACKGROUND)
Do they like each other now?
Are you kidding me?
They can't stand
being in the same room.
I also don't think
they can handle being apart.
And I think
they just found a way
to avoid doing either.
And that's the best
most fathers and sons
can do.
(GASPS)
(CHOKED UP)
You've made me
so proud today.
Ugh.
Does anyone know
where we can buy
a real sword?
Oh, Jeffrey.
(CHUCKLES)
You're still at the entrance
to the chamber of grief.
Your move, Mr. Tickles.
You successfully pour more tea
into Count Frogula's cup.
That puts it
at Hillary Rodham kitten.
Okay, you attempt
to pass crumpets.
You fail.
Okay, guys, I'm getting
a little frustrated.
If you'd just take a look
at your inventories,
you'll see that...
Abed, are you almost done?
I can't sleep
without my stuffies.
Fine. Hold on.
Oh, a goblin notices you
and murders you all.
You're dead.
They're all yours.