So according
to the demonologist,
the gymnasium is clean.
Jeez, we're running out
of to-do stars.
Already dealt with.
JEFF: It's hard to believe.
Somewhere along the way,
we started turning
this school around.
Huh.
Hmm.
What the hell was that?
What was what?
That long, quiet lull.
I don't like it.
It's called contentment,
dude.
Exactly. We're never content.
Someone's always got to
have a problem.
I've got a problem.
I don't like Abed's problem
with our lack of problems.
Ooh.
Oh. Ah, okay.
(LAUGHING)
I commented on his commentary.
I just drew a circle
around Abed, baby.
(SWEET VOICE)
I don't think it's nice
to pigeonhole
people's gimmicks.
(DEEP VOICE)
You hear me, two voice?
Abed, let us have a moment
of peace and stillness.
They're kind of rare
around here.
All I'm saying is,
calm before the storm.
Says the storm generator.
All right, fine.
Let's be content.
Hmm. Hmm.
PELTON: (OVER PA)
Attention, students
and faculty of Greendale.
I pressed this button
on accident
but might as well check in.
How are you?
ALL:  Fine.
PELTON:  Aw, that's nice.
I'm good too.
I love you guys.
ALL:  We love you too.
♪ Give me some rope
tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
WOMAN:  The information
you have requested...
MAN:  Is on the internet.
(GROANING) Oh.
School board, baby.
School board guys coming in.
I would appreciate
some knocking.
Do you know what goes on
in here?
Just a heads-up.
There's an insurance
appraiser coming tomorrow.
Your ass
is getting appraised
insurance-style.
(LAUGHS)
What does that mean?
We hope it means
we find out that
your school
is very, very valuable
to the city.
Hey,
how hilarious would that be?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Are you guys drunk?
Good luck proving it
before we're not.
Yeah.
(SCOFFS)
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
MALE VOICE:
Papapapaya. Whoa!
Heh.
Strawberry.
FEMALE VOICE:  Too ripe.
You guys have been doing this
for 30 minutes.
So what?
I made all the vegetables
disappear.
Usually, a lot more than this
happens in 30 minutes
is all I'm saying.
We're just relaxed and happy.
I care more about this
than anything I've ever
cared about.
Best $199 I've ever spent.
It's three dollars.
What are you playing?
That's control software
for some kind of
irrigation equipment.
It's fun.
Save Greendale committee,
unite.
Boom.
An insurance appraiser
is coming tomorrow
to inspect the school,
and if he doesn't
appraise us good,
the school is doomed,
doomed.
Call to adventure.
What's an insurance appraiser?
Something that sounds
normal and boring
but is actually scary,
like a raised mole
or a turkey deep fryer.
There's only one man
qualified to appraise
insurance,
and he died 2,000 years ago
on a cross.
I've seen
insurance appraisers bleed.
Their blood's different,
darker.
Everyone, take a breath.
You're overreacting
because this school
is addicted to crisis.
They're like one
of those hurricane
Katrina dogs
that won't let anyone
pet them anymore.
JEFF: But the weird thing
we need to get used to
is this:
The school's in decent shape.
This doesn't have to be
a big deal.
I wrote a paper
on those dogs.
We've worked hard all semester
to save this school.
Truth is, we did.
So relax.
Are you sure, Jeffrey?
I promise.
Jeff's heart is in
the right place,
but he's wrong.
Greendale is a crazy place
where crazy things happen.
I have a plan.
We'll pretend our school
has a world renowned
physics department.
Dean,
start learning Swedish.
I'll do my best!
Hickey, do you keep in touch
with any unstable criminals
that you busted?
Mmm, five.
Get them down here
for costume measurements.
Annie, we need to make
a particle accelerator
out of Kleenex boxes.
Nope.
Nobody do any of that.
Abed, outside.
There is no story.
Everything's a story, Jeff.
Getting out of bed is a story.
Certainly this is a story.
I mean, start with
the study room.
We're content.
I'm concerned.
Skip the fruit-matching stuff.
Dean enters with
the insurance appraiser story,
call, refusal.
You're literally dragging me
across a threshold
demanding there be no story,
which puts me
into a whole new world
that I'm gonna have to
adapt to.
Well, you have to do it
by yourself, please.
Okay?
Because if this appraisal
is a story,
that means we're in trouble,
and we are not in trouble,
because if we are...
No more stories.
Tada.
So we'll see you later.
After no story.
No story.
So be it.
Let the lack of story...
(SLURPING)
Hey.
Oh, put one trap
behind each cabinet.
Although
I think we're good.
The cafeteria food killed
most of the roaches anyway.
JEFF: Hey, check it out.
Is this a wedding ring?
PELTON: Are you kidding?
What...
Aw...
I lost this
my first week here.
Oh,
who's the lucky...
It's my mom's.
I started wearing it
because... I don't know.
Everybody dreams
of settling down, right?
And because it fits.
She had huge fingers
for a woman,
part of what killed her,
really.
I'm not dreaming
about settling down.
Well,
maybe you already have.
You're teaching,
and you like it.
You love Greendale.
No,
I love scotch and myself.
I tolerate Greendale.
It's a good school.
That's why there's no need
for this to get sentimental.
This inspection is going to be
the most boring thing
to happen here
since Britta dated Troy.
All right, no story.
Wait.
If there's no story,
what am I explaining?
I'm in a story.
Okay, think, Abed, think.
How do you shake a story?
The answer
is in the teacher's lounge.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Here he comes,
here he comes.
Okay.
Hi, there.
My name is Ronald Mohammed.
Go ahead.
I've heard them all.
RONALD: The city of Greendale
has sent me here
to assess this campus' level
of liability.
Now,
what do I mean by liability?
Well, the city
defines liability
as any asserted
or non-asserted perturbation
by any qualifying party.
What's a party?
A party is a person
or a group of persons
or an event
celebrating a person
or a party of persons' birth,
marriage...
Don't panic, Jeffrey.
Hmm?
I'm fine.
I'm the only one
who's not panicking.
Oh, please.
You can lie to yourself,
but don't lie to me.
But the city defines a dog
as any living entity
with four legs and a tail,
so raccoons, bears,
mountain lions, mice
these are all just
different sizes of dog.
What do I mean by "size"?
I'll tell you a story.
What's that
supposed to mean?
I know how much you feel
for the campus, Jeff.
in general.
And I know you think
it's a weakness,
but believe me,
it's your strength.
You got something
in your teeth.
Mmm-hmm, you got something
in your chest.
400,000 gallons
of liquefied horse meat.
Here I come.
Just...
"And you shall find
that salt is the taste
"of another man's bread,
"and hard is the way
up and down
another man's stairs."
Dante. Let's proceed.
(GASPS)
(SHOUTING) No!
It's always a story.
Everything is a story.
(WHIMPERING)
Wait. Wait. wait.
Story feeds on conflict.
If I stop resisting,
it'll stop being a story.
No, Abed.
Me with a beard?
Keep fighting the story.
Keep fighting it
until it falls apart.
I'm right.
I mean I'm wrong.
I mean I'm right.
Unsubscribe.
For the final stage
of my appraisal,
I am going to randomly select
one of your vending machines
to see if it can be rocked
using human strength
enough to tip and crush me.
Now, in the U.S., each year,
six people die this way,
and five of them
are insurance appraisers,
so I take this very seriously.
Here we go.
(GRUNTS)
Okay.
Whoo!
MAN: Sorry we're late.
Hey, look.
It's Ronald Mohammed.
How about that name?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
MAN: All right, Ronald,
what's the damage?
How much is this scampy,
little hole in the earth
gonna cost us this year?
Well,
your gas leak is repaired,
all your fire exits
actually lead outside,
and I am told
that no new species
have been discovered here
in a week.
I have to say, I was
brought in here to estimate
Greendale's liability,
but at this point in time,
I'd describe this campus
as an actual property asset.
This property has value.
(ALL CHEERING)
CHANG: Yeah!
SHIRLEY: Best news ever!
(ANTS MARCHING PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
This property has value.
It has value.
That means we can sell it!
We can finally sell it!
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
Press "stop" on Dave Matthews.
What did you just say?
We can start
courting businesses
to unload this school
on the private sector.
What do you mean "unload it"?
This is a huge chunk
of real estate,
which generates
no tax revenue
and takes money
from the education budget.
That's because it's
a community college.
Well, excuse us
for taking longer
to see that was the problem.
Maybe we're not
as smart as you.
I mean,
we only went to Yale.
Oh, no, you didn't.
MAN1: Yes, I did.
MAN2: Oh!
Oh, hey, we should call
T.J. Maxx right away.
Dude, I told you.
This jacket looks fine.
No, to talk about
selling this place.
Oh, right.
Yeah, T.J. Maxx, Marshalls.
What about Ben &amp; Jerry's?
Oh, Richie,
you're my friend,
but that is the last thing
you need.
(SIGHS)
Tough love received, bro.
(SOMBER MUSIC)
I did it.
This school is story-free.
We can be content now forever.
(SIGHS)
Ahhh!
(GRUNTING)
Let me be one of the six
this year.
Craig, Craig, this vending
machine is not gonna
tip over and crush you.
Why not?
Why?
Because we fixed it
when we saved Greendale.
We saved Greendale.
And now they're gonna sell it.
(SOBS)
(ANTS MARCHING PLAYING)
♪ He wakes up
in the morning
If I come over there,
there are gonna be
two sounds...
Me hitting you twice.
♪ Never changes a... ♪
PELTON:  Hello, Greendale,
as you know,
our school will soon
be replaced by
a sandwich university.
However, every ending
is also a beginning.
Sure,
things may look bad now.
Some of us may have
no idea where we're going
or what to do.
But...
Okay, okay,
I should have
written this out.
I thought I'd be able
to come up with something
on the fly.
Moving on to phase two:
The actual saving
of Greendale.
Annie...
I've generated a few ideas
involving social media
that I think
might do the trick.
Annie...
You want us to tweet
"save Greendale"?
I'm sorry, Annie.
The reason I have 48 followers
is that I don't exploit them.
They come to me
for atheistic rants and photos
of my meals,
not this obnoxiousness.
We need to make people aware
that Greendale exists
and needs help.
Why?
Because once the internet
knows about something,
it changes.
Right.
Just ask Chris Brown or China.
(SOBBING)
Jeff,
you made Annie cry.
Well, if it's any consolation,
this is the last time
that will ever happen.
(SOBBING)
I know
how to save Greendale.
Treasure.
Buried treasure.
Okay, I'm tapped.
We all wish we could
do something, Annie,
but I think that concludes
the last meeting
of the save Greendale
committee,
the committee that did
its darnedest.
Wait.
Are we sure
we can't stop the school
from being sold to subway?
I'm afraid so, Chang.
Okay,
I just wanted to make sure.
Haha,
screw you guys.
It's time to get paid.
♪ Five dollar
♪ Five dollar foot-long
♪ Any, any, any, five
CHANG:
♪ Five dollar foot-long
♪ Any, any, any, five ♪
Chang just unexpectedly
betrayed the group
for the last time.
(SIGHS)
(ANNIE SOBBING)
Greendale is going to make
a great Subway
sandwich university.
You know, research
shows most of
your graduates
end up working for
our restaurants anyway.
That's by design.
We're very proud
of our school.
Proud of Subway's school.
This campus is yours now.
If you want to dynamite it,
all we ask is that you let us
light the fuse.
Yeah, we hate this place.
You just said
you were proud of it.
Oh, proud of its potential.
Love its potential.
This will be your office.
(SOBBING)
Why?
Okay,
we'll check in on that later.
What's the matter, guys?
Can't wait until
Greendale's corpse is cold
before you put it
on a six inch white bun?
Young lady,
that's not fair.
Subway doesn't call
its bread "buns,"
and we don't serve white.
We serve Italian, honey oat,
nine-grain wheat.
Great, thanks for making
my joke accurate.
Now it's hilarious.
Classes are over, kids.
We're helping the Dean pack.
This is still Greendale
for two hours.
Enjoy it.
Wait.
You don't call
your bread "buns."
What do you call them?
Bread.
Well, bread is a substance.
What do you call the units
of bread you use, "breads"?
(PELTON SOBBING)
You okay?
I just wish we had more time.
I could turn things around.
I swear.
Look, I got
one of these label things.
It makes custom labels.
This was gonna help me
get organized. (SOBS)
ANNIE: Aw.
Where should we start?
Should we pack up
these pictures?
They're not really mine.
They're Greendale history.
Here's our 1987
civil rights march.
This was when we started
offering Photoshop classes.
And that's Russell Borchert.
Oh.
BOTH:
"Borchert, Borchert,
loved computers"
Yes, yes,
"More than women's butts
or hooters."
Very mature,
you two.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Was there any truth
to that legend?
The legend that
a Greendale computer professor
made love to a computer
and died of the first
computer virus? Sure.
The truth is, Greendale
had a computer professor.
By the way,
he was a millionaire
and a genius.
He has sex with one computer,
and that's his legacy?
So after all my work,
how will I be remembered?
The bald dean with glasses,
I guess.
Are you aware
there's an engraved plate
on this frame
that says "the truth is
behind this picture"?
Of course I'm aware, Abed.
I'm not an idiot.
(GASPS)
Whoa, wait.
It meant literally?
ANNIE: What is it?
(COUGHS)
(ALL GASPING)
I understand you were teaching
fundamentals of law here.
Yeah.
Think you could
make the transition
to teaching sandwich law?
It's essentially the same,
I'm sure,
just a bit more focused.
Here.
That's a Subway black card.
It entitles you
to five dollar foot-longs
for life.
For life, Mr. Winger,
(SOFT MUSIC)
Hey.
(SIGHS)
So...
What are you going to do?
I'm thinking I'm gonna
transfer to city college,
but I'm knowing
I'm gonna be a bartender.
(CHUCKLES)
You?
Subway offered me a job.
Nice.
I'm worried about
Abed and Annie.
They're not ready
for this to end.
Yeah, they're part
of the adulthood
begins at 30 generation.
I'm... I'm actually
looking forward
to a little bit of...
Sanity?
Yes, sanity.
Yeah, I mean, it's over,
but on the other hand,
it's over.
Amen.
And to think this all started
because you wanted to...
Nail you.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah,
I regret nothing.
Don't.
I mean, after everything
that has happened here,
what did either of us
really get done
aside from each other?
Exactly, and what are either
of us gonna be leaving with?
Um, I should go clean out
my locker,
she said at the age of 33.
Let's get married.
What?
Yeah, right?
I mean,
this is what matters,
isn't it?
This is what keeps this all
from being pointless.
Let's do what people do.
Let's get a house
we can't afford
and a dog that makes us angry.
And dedicate an entire cabinet
to grocery bags
and realize we have
a favorite brand of olive oil?
Yes, marry me.
Okay, yeah.
Yeah, uh, yeah,
this feels right.
Let's get out of here
and never look back.
Yeah, but first,
let's lock these doors
and pull these shades.
We've never had sex
on the new table.
Yes,
two for two.
Medium roughness,
high tempo?
Let's make it
a number eight.
Buried treasure!
ANNIE: Whoo!
Lock the doors.
Close the blinds.
We could save Greendale, Jeff.
There may be treasure
on campus.
Hidden, buried treasure.
PELTON: Treasure!
We need to call
an emergency meeting
somewhere safe where no one
can hear or see,
because we have to
keep this a secret,
because it's a buried...
BOTH: Treasure!
Buried treasure!
♪ Buried treasure,
buried treasure
ALL:
♪ Buried treasure,
buried treasure
buried treasure ♪
Interesting.
Emergency meeting.
(CACKLING)
And that's how I ended up
at Greendale.
Isn't it strange how it took
this school shutting down
for you and I to finally
get to know each other?
So what's up next for you?
Don't know, maybe go stay
with family in Lincolnshire.
Lincolnshire?
Yeah.
Where in Lincolnshire?
Just a little town
called Scunthorpe.
Scunthorpe?
I was stationed
around Scunthorpe.
No.
Oh, wait, wait.
♪ O'er the lady's smocks
I tarry
♪ Through the hollyhocks
and glen
BOTH:
♪ For a piss and a thrush
in Scunthorpe
♪ Then it's off
to Henningpen ♪
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I love that.
Oh, where in god's name
did you learn that song?
Stainsbury pub.
My family practically
lived in Stainsbury's.
I lost my virginity
at Stainsbury's.
My mother was
a Stainsbury whore.
(LAUGHS)
Mine was missing a thumb.
Oh, my God.
(LAUGHS)
Two thumbs, yeah,
she got both.
Two thumbs.
I mean, you may have
slept with my aunt,
but given the circumstances,
cheers.
Cheers, yeah.
Yeah.
Mmm, so you're gonna
stay with your family
till you get your bearings?
I've got a cousin, Clive,
who's got a spare room.
You and he would really
get along, actually.
Really?
Yeah.
Did you get any of that?