PELTON:
This is Russell Borchert,
computer genius,
anti-deodorant activist,
and millionaire.
He was rich
for having invented
the 9-track cassette,
which the 8-track industry
paid to keep quiet.
He funneled that wealth
into a computer school
called Greendale,
where he obsessively
pursued a new project,
a machine that can
process feelings.
He apparently used
nothing but gold
to assemble his circuitry,
believing it to be
a better conductor
of human emotion.
It was a weird time.
The Bionic Woman
won an Emmy.
ANNIE: Rumors spread
about his relationship
with computers,
and one day,
he disappeared,
hence the legend
that he died of
the first computer virus.
The city bought the campus,
and life went on.
PELTON:
His body was never found,
nor was his immense wealth.
Some people said
he hid his money
using a portal
to another dimension.
Those people were on LSD.
Everyone else said
he had a secret vault
in his office.
Well, where's his office?
Good question.
We found this confession
written by Greendale's
first dean.
"To protect
the student health and
the school's reputation,
"I have sealed off
the computer department
"and removed the stairwell
to that entire section."
A section that remains
on this campus somewhere,
its secrets untouched,
including quite possibly
Borchert's millions.
If we found it,
we could buy it
from the city
before Subway.
Then I could really go nuts
with this place.
This is the kind
of adventure I usually
have to force upon us,
and here it is,
falling into our laps.
We're like  The Goonies,
except our story
tracks logically
and has a chance
of holding up to objective
critical scrutiny.
(ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
Can you
please stop that?
Sorry.
Here are your blueprints.
Sorry it took so long.
You can't fight city hall.
Uh, apparently you can.
That's why it took so long.
Well, I'll be damned.
Would you look at that?
It's so clear now.
The entire school
is shaped like a penis.
No, that.
It says right here
that this stairway
leads to sublevel three.
ANNIE: Is that where
the teachers' lounge is?
(GASPING)
What the hell
does your penis
look like?
Obviously a cluster
of buildings,
so let's all
have a big laugh
at the freak.
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream
♪ Give me the hope
to run out of steam
♪ Somebody said
it can be here
♪ We could be roped up,
tied up, dead in a year
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay
♪ One by one they all
just fade away ♪
The missing stairwell
would be in this area.
Keep your eyes peeled.
I don't know why,
but serial killers
and people
that hide treasure
always leave
weird little clues.
Check it out.
Look at the bottle
held by the school's
first and least
acceptable mascot,
Big Chief Drunky.
X marks the spot, baby.
(ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
JEFF: Maybe you
shouldn't be...
Okay.
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
Shirley, will you
lock the door?
Okay.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(SQUEALING)
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
There you go.
It's just a bunch of wires.
Exactly what they want us
to think.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, my God.
(SCREAMING)
Wait, wait, wait.
The sparks
may be spelling out
the next clue.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Is Duncan okay?
He'll live,
but his food's gonna
taste like burnt aluminum
for a while.
It's pronounced
al-u-minium.
See, he's fine.
Okay, guys, stop it now.
Nobody wants to admit
it's over,
but come on.
Oh, look,
it's Jeff Winger,
fun police,
here to pull over
our smiles
'cause our mouths
have tinted windows.
Britta and I
are getting married.
What?
Married?
Well, you're gonna need
way more doves than this.
PELTON:
What does this look like,
an hour-long episode
of  The Office?
There's pick-axing
and electric zapping.
ANNIE: Don't even
acknowledge it.
We are not
acknowledging this.
You guys
are ridiculous together.
We're ridiculous?
What do you call this?
Secret trapdoor!
Booyah.
Who's got rope?
I'm offended
by that question.
(GRUNTING)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
This is Richie and Carl
from the school board.
That's right.
We got names.
Open this door now.
CHANG: Wait, I know
where the keys are.
CARL: You hear that?
When we get there,
you're gonna be
in big trouble.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Here they are.
Which one is it?
Well, it's never
the first one,
so we can cancel
this one out.
Come on.
I guess now
this is the first one,
so it should be
the next one.
Oh, damn.
You know what?
I got it.
Get out of the way.
Richie, be careful.
Don't worry.
I've been drinking.
(SHOUTING)
Oh, hello.
Would you like some tea?
HICKEY: The tea is swell.
Do you think they...
(SHUSHING)
I think...
Oh, come on, shh.
(SHUSHING)
(BOTH SHUSHING)
You know
it's just as loud as...
(BOTH SHUSHING)
(ALL SHUSHING)
(SHOUTING)
Everybody, shut up!
ABED: Guys, I think
this is the lost section
of Greendale.
Nobody's been in here
since the '70s.
How do you know?
ABED: Because the
debate team topic is,
"Who's hotter, Elliot Gould
or Donald Sutherland?"
BOTH: Donald Sutherland.
ANNIE: Scary.
PELTON: Oh, relax.
If it's anything
like a regular dungeon,
it's only as dangerous
as whoever invited you.
Abed, if there's
killer robots down here,
you'll tell them
we're on your side, right?
Yes, but we won't know them
from ordinary robots
until they kill us.
BRITTA: So what do
we do now?
Split up.
Leave no '70s reference
unturned.
This decade's a little out
of my wheelhouse.
Pet rock...
Leave no pet rock unturned.
BRITTA: Here, let me lead,
my light's better.
JEFF: Your light's better?
You're that insecure
that your light
has to be better?
BRITTA: Shut up.
JEFF: You shut up.
Anything in there?
Just spider webs
and beanbag chairs.
Oh, don't cry.
The importance
of lumbar support hadn't...
It's not that.
It's just even if
we do save Greendale,
which Greendale
will we be saving?
First Pierce dies,
then Troy leaves.
Now people are...
Getting married?
Annie, look,
I don't know people,
but I know TV.
When characters feel
like the show they're on
is ending,
their instinct is to spin off
into something safer,
in Jeff and Britta's case,
something that would last
six episodes
and have a lot of bickering
about tweezers and gluten,
starring them
and an equally
waspy brunette couple
with a title like
Better With My Worse Half
or  Awfully Wedded
or  Tying The Not,
but "knot" is spelt
without a k,
or  #Couple People Problems...
Abed.
And every episode,
you get...
Abed.
Abed, stop developing.
Sorry.
The point is,
this show, Annie,
it isn't just their show.
This is our show,
and it's not over.
And the sooner
we find that treasure,
the faster
the Jeff-Britta pilot
falls apart.
Got it.
Thank you, Abed.
You're welcome.
I have a girlfriend.
What?
You were about to start
a kiss lean.
I was not.
Fine.
Let's go find treasure.
ABED: Did you
find anything?
PELTON: No.
We've searched
every crevice
of this place,
and the only treasures
we've found
are this CB radio,
these basketball cards
with white people on them,
and this
little rocket launcher
from some action figure.
(GAGGING)
Seems like an odd place
for a dead end, though.
Could be a secret door.
Maybe the jukebox
is the key to it.
Just remember,
it's okay if we fail.
Right, Jeff?
That's right.
Ugh, try every button.
Just try every
single button ever.
(SPITTING)
(GASPING)
Are you all right?
(SHOUTING) No!
I was dying!
Try track 127.
Right.
Because 127 in binary code
would be a palindrome.
Because the song title
is  Open The Door
by The Secret Doors.
(FUNKY DISCO MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Open the door,
yeah, sweet mama
♪ We got to open the door
♪ And the door is opening
♪ You're playing the song
that opens the door
♪ We recorded this song
for when you open the door
♪ Specially timed
to the duration
♪ Of the opening process ♪
ABED: Borchert's secret lab.
That's the machine
Borchert was working on
in the film.
Borchert's gold.
We need
to get this upstairs.
Save Greendale.
(CHITTERING)
(SCREAMING)
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
You're Russell Borchert,
aren't you?
Hey, I'm gonna peel off
some Band-Aids here.
Dennis Hopper is dead,
TV shows give no time
for theme songs anymore,
and Woody Allen
did the voice
of a cartoon ant.
(GROWLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Jeff!
Sorry, I lose track
of how big I'm getting.
I don't.
You vandalized
private property.
You nearly
destroy the school.
When it's finally about
to make a profit?
You guys are the worst,
with your stupid paintballs
and your freeze tags.
Hot lava.
That was hot lava?
Dumb.
(SNARLING)
Tell us
where the others went.
Guys, guys.
RICHIE: What do you
want to do?
CARL: What should we do?
CHANG: Well, what can we do?
Okay.
I'm gonna need you guys
to stay back,
and never tell anyone
about what you
saw here today.
(PANTING)
WOMAN:  Richie. Richie.
You're special, Richie.
Your mind is special.
You know it
works differently
from other kids' minds.
CHILDREN:
♪ Richie's a freak
♪ Richie's a freak ♪
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
Thank you.
I know where they went.
They climbed out a window
to the roof,
hopped on a hang glider,
and flew it across town
to that Greek restaurant,
Papa Cristo's?
I robbed your brain.
I robbed it.
Hey, guys,
we found a hatch
in the floor
underneath
the vending machine.
I think
they went down inside it.
Was there a hang glider?
Uh, you're gonna
find out...
You're gonna find
a hang glider
down there.
That much I know.
So anyway,
I sealed myself up
down here
with 50 years of food,
50 years of toilet paper,
and 50 years of cocaine,
which I somehow ran out of
after about 10 years.
Wow, the '80s happened
down here too.
Yeah.
Hey, what are you doing
with Raquel?
(GRUNTING)
Russell, we're on
a bit of a deadline,
and to put it bluntly,
we need your gold.
Raquel!
BRITTA: Uh, guys,
little help...
She just needs
a little more time.
Sir, Raquel has taken
the best years of your life
and a dozen
of your not-so-good.
If she hasn't given
anything back,
it might be time
to move on.
Stop.
You guys...
What are we doing?
Saving Greendale.
From what?
We were driven
down here
by sellouts
with crappy values.
Since when do
human beings decide
which dreams
are worthwhile?
Look at him.
He's one of us.
We have to respect
each other enough
to let each other want
what we want,
no matter how transparently
self-destructive
or empty
our desires may be.
If it was money
that you guys wanted,
why didn't you say so?
You can just have
my leftover cash
that's under the desk
over there.
Yeah, I don't think
it's worth much up there.
Those are
Gerald Ford dollars.
How many?
Eh, couple of million.
Back in the '70s,
that was worth millions.
Hey, I've got an idea.
How about you people
leave me alone,
and I hereby grant that
to Greendale?
(LAUGHING)
PELTON: What?
(ALL CHEERING)
Glad to hear it.
Get back.
This pickle's a magnet.
Whoa, whoa.
I'll wipe her out, man.
Don't you dare use
that pickle magnet on her.
(BOTH TALKING AT ONCE)
Stop. Don't do it.
Get over there
with them.
You have no legal claim
to that money.
Take it up with Subway
in about an hour...
After close of escrow.
Hey, Chang,
you've become
a bad guy again?
There's a lot more to it
than that, Britta.
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
Wait, I'm not wearing
a mask?
Okay, there's
no more to it.
I think I'm just
mentally ill.
All right, just stay back.
All right?
No, don't.
(SCREAMING) No!
♪ Yeah, sweet mama
we got to close the door
♪ The door is closing
♪ Faster than it opens
♪ For dramatic effect ♪
Hey!
RUSSELL:
Hang in there.
Raquel is
the main operating system.
She controls the door,
the lights,
the shower probably,
everything.
And now she's dead.
(CRYING)
So we're trapped
in here forever.
Or just until
we run out of
food and water.
At least
we'll have each other.
Till death do us part.
You know what?
You guys can have
my food and water.
RUSSELL: Come on, Raquel.
Come on.
Baby. Come on.
(GROANING)
(POWERING UP)
(LAUGHING)
Oh, thank God.
Her emotional components
are still on-line.
Emotional components?
I have accomplished things
down here,
you couldn't
even possibly imagine.
Here, let me show you.
Ah, right there!
That was it.
Did you see it?
Don't you see?
This computer
responds to feelings.
When I started Greendale,
it was for ordinary people
to be able
to access technology.
Wait, you started Greendale.
Do you have that
in writing anywhere?
I don't know.
Somewhere with
all that crap over there.
But without
an emotional component,
computers would strip us
of all humanity
and create a society
with emotionless eggheads
at the top
and idiots with feelings
at the bottom,
and I refuse
to let that happen,
and that's why I've spent...
What? What is that?
It's a video of a kitten.
RUSSELL: And why are
those people
arguing about it?
And what's that?
That's an emoticon.
That person wants
to indicate happiness
but can't convey it
with language,
so they misuse punctuation
to form a smile.
(SIGHING)
That is so...
Stupid.
Only an idiot
would think of this.
Idiots won.
Which means
my work down here
is done.
Good, because according
to what I'm seeing,
if we can get you up there
right now,
Subway won't be
buying this school.
What?
Uh, yeah,
but it's gonna take
a few hours
to get that door open,
because Raquel's
logic circuits...
Bleh, not good.
You said her emotional
components work.
Well, in theory,
a blast of human passion
could shock the mainframe
into a cold start,
but that's only if
somebody in this room
has feelings
stronger than I get
when I rub my nipples.
So good luck
with that, folks.
Give me that.
Everybody over there.
Turn around.
Turn around now.
PELTON:
You're here to save me,
aren't you?
BRITTA:  Let's get out of here
and never look back.
ABED:  Jeff, in case
you ever have
to remember me,
can I give you
some options
for voice-over quotes?
JEFF:  Shut up, Abed.
JEFF:  Milady.
ANNIE:  Milord.
(MACHINES WHIRRING)
What did you do?
Don't worry about it.
Let's go.
CARL: The city of Greendale
is proud
to be selling the school
of Greendale to Subway.
This brings to an end
several years
of horrible management
by Dean Craig Isidore Pelton.
Not to throw anyone
under the bus,
but he'd be the one.
No.
And by my watch,
it is about time
to sign these documents
and make it official.
JEFF: Objection!
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
I teach law at Greendale,
so believe me,
I don't know much
about law,
but I do know
a contract violation
when I see one.
This is
a legitimate transaction
where a city
is selling a school
to a restaurant.
It happens somewhere
every day.
Oh, the city can sell
the school all it wants,
but according
to his contract
with the city,
the school's
original founder
retains the privilege
of consultation
on all future
scholastic endeavors
taking place here.
So Subway
sandwich university,
meet your new vice dean,
Russell Borchert.
Oh!
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
(MUMBLING)
(CLEARING THROAT)
(SNORTING)
Hi.
I guess we're gonna
be partners.
I understand
there's some internet
where I can make
my inner thoughts public.
Uh, It seems like
Greendale the city
and Greendale the school
have some stuff
to sort out,
and Subway doesn't...
Doesn't do conflict.
We do good food
at good prices.
We are but simple
sandwich artists
who want the world
to eat fresh.
ALL: Eat fresh.
Subway...ho!
Did we just
save Greendale?
Did we just save Greendale?
No, no, you did not.
You moved dirt
around Greendale's grave.
Your school
is still bankrupt,
it is still unmarketable,
and it is still on
the permanent
chopping block
of anyone who has
any say in its future.
Yeah?
Well, around here,
we call that Wednesday.
(ALL CHEERING)
(PEPPY MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ He wakes up
♪ In the morning
(ALL IMITATING
DAVE MATTHEWS SINGING)
♪ Never changes a thing ♪
Hey, after I
was electrocuted,
didn't you two say
you were gonna
get married?
Doesn't electrocuted
technically mean killed?
Do you always
have to correct people
like that?
Do you always have
to police correcting?
That's it,
the marriage is off.
I think you mean
the wedding is off.
Yeah!
Hey, hey.
Hey, I got to say,
you held up well
under that interrogation.
(GIGGLING)
I'm gonna tell you
something
that I'd like to stay
between us.
Oh.
I was thinking about
a hang glider.
None of this conflict
truly matters.
The only owners
of this land
are the Arapaho.
Would it offend you
if I asked you
to train me in the use
of certain powers?
Sorry, Carl.
You deserve better.
Chang, you get it.
How would you like a job
on the school board?
Okay.
Your first job
is to deliver this
to the city bursar's office.
On it.
Hi, yes, I'd like
to replace all my teeth
with diamonds.
We live to fight
another day.
Speaking of days,
I never got a chance
to wish you
a Happy Birthday
or Halloween or Christmas,
or any specific
calendar event.
Well, maybe next year.
Definitely.
We'll definitely be back
next year.
If not, it'll be
because an asteroid
has destroyed
all human civilization,
and that's Canon.
What? What are you...
Hmm? Nothing.
(IMITATING
DAVE MATTHEWS SINGING)
♪ Lights down,
you up and die ♪
Am I thinking
what you're thinking?
(WHISPERING)
Penny for your thoughts.
Intensive Karen.
Mr. Egypt.
Celebrity beat-off.
Captain Cook.
ALL: Depends on
what fails.
Did you get any of that?