Chomsky, come here.
Come here, Chomsky.
-Abed, I'm really sorry.
ABED: I told you cats don't like me.
They consider me a competitor because
of my stealth and ambivalence.
Uh-oh. Did she get high again
and forget she doesn't wear contacts?
ANNIE: Before Britta moved her cats
into our apartment,
she wanted to introduce them to us
on neutral ground.
One of them scratched Abed
and ran under the couch.
Oh. I'll get it. Cats love me.
-What? Are you sure?
CHANG: Mm-hm.
Hello there.
-Well, she is-- Is it a he or a she?
BRITTA: He.
Well, he's really got his teeth
in my flesh right now.
Okay, he's touching bone.
I'm just waiting for him to finish up.
Not a lot I can do at this point.
This was a pretty big mistake.
Okay, I guess he's done.
Oh!
See you tomorrow.
-I'm pretty embarrassed about this.
BRITTA: Chomsky--
I didn't know Britta was moving in
with Annie and Abed. That's--
Expository? Britta's fallen on hard times
and our apartment is the cheapest game.
Abed, it's a little embarrassing
when you put it that way.
Britta's a rich genius with superpowers
and gonna live on our sofa for no reason.
Oh, no, dinosaurs.
My tax documents.
Facts about Native Americans.
Just kidding.
Guess what I just purchased
for the school from a local manufacturer.
Greendale's first virtual reality
operating system.
Did Greendale need
a virtual reality system?
Uh, like a hole in the head.
Hole in the head is something
that you don't need.
She said through a huge hole
in her head.
Didn't VR go out in the '90s?
The last people I saw using it
were in the Honeycomb Hideout.
-Mock what we don't understand.
-Also what's silly.
Jeffrey.
Abed, you're more machine than man.
You wanna give me a hand setting up
the equipment after lunch?
We're all gonna help Britta
move into our place today.
PELTON: Jeffrey?
-Britta, something's come up.
-I'd love to.
-Ah.
Yeah. At least you don't have to bust out
your usual excuse.
You don't know for sure
that I'm not a veteran.
Nobody can say for sure
that today isn't Veterans Day.
Hi, I got bit by a cat.
Chang, we know.
Why are you guys and all these books
in the nurse's office?
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE"
PLAYING]
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up, tied up
Dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪♪
FRANKIE: Dean, where did you get this
and for how much of the school's money?
Oh, relax, my little bean countess.
Don't worry about it.
You pay me to worry about that.
Oh, and how much do I pay you?
That's you.
It was only $5000.
-What?
-Frankie, jack me up.
I would like to see
this company's website.
-Can I use your computer?
-Sure.
Have fun in the Stone Age
while I step into the third Dean-mension.
-Width?
-No. Read the instructions, Analog Man.
"When entering virtual reality,
calibrate the system
by looking at your own hands,
then turning them over
and looking at the backs of them
-with a sense of wonder."
-Roger that.
[BEEPING]
COMPUTER:
Welcome to the VirtuGood 6500.
[GASPS]
COMPUTER: Initiate calibration.
PELTON: My God.
It's incredible.
I can see all around.
Let me take a closer look
at these structures. I--
[PELTON LAUGHING]
I'm walking.
I am walking.
My God.
I know what this is.
[PELTON LAUGHS]
I set the time zone.
-I set the time zone.
-And my phone does that automatically.
I'm gonna see
if I can make the font bigger.
The font is larger.
And Jesus wept,
for there were no more worlds to conquer.
[♪♪♪]
Thank you guys again so much.
I know that I already owe you money,
but I got a new bartending job
with better hours and free corn nuts,
which have a small
but significant resale value.
I feel like everybody's talking
about that haircut I gave Vicki, so--
-Oh, Britta, it's okay.
-Can I--? Do I do this too? Okay.
This is gonna be good for all of us, right?
It's like a fresh start.
-Oh, did you guys get a new couch?
-We got it for you. It has a pull-out.
You guys.
Wanted a Murphy bed for shenanigans,
but cost-to-shenanigan ratio was high.
How did you guys afford this?
Oh, don't worry.
We got a good deal.
BRITTA: "For pickup, Perry."
Why is my name on here?
Because we got it for you.
And we told the sales guy that, so...
So he put your friend's name
on the delivery slip?
That seems weird, right?
-Roommate movie night.
-Roommate movie night! Yay!
-Portuguese Gremlins.
-Portuguese Gremlins. Ooh.
Portugal's answer,
if Gremlins' question was:
"How can you rip us off without spending money,
having watched maybe twice?"
Chee-choo, chee-choo.
-What the Portuguese gremlins say.
-Close enough.
ANNIE:
Chee-choo, chee-choo.
[GRUNTING]
I did it.
It's 2:39.
That was the time
when you started setting the time.
It's 20 minutes later now.
The power, the facility.
-Jesus wep--
-Stop saying, "Jesus wept."
Dean, here's something fun
you might want to try.
Let's see if we can find the serial number
to this system.
Oh, that could be fun.
So go to Settings.
Is Settings the volcano
or the cobbler's workshop?
It's a monastery.
[CHUCKLING]
PELTON:
I feel the power!
[GRUNTS]
COMPUTER:
Welcome to Settings.
[GASPS]
PELTON:
The majesty, the filing cabinets.
JEFF: You're looking for one
called Purchase Info.
[GRUNTING]
[LAUGHING]
PELTON: These wouldn't be this easy
to climb in real life. Future of scrolling.
My world is officially boundless.
Ha! I'm here.
Inside that drawer should be a file
called Serial Number.
[GASPS]
PELTON:
I've got it.
All right, now you just have
to print that file out.
You can do that by dragging it
to the Accessories
and Peripherals castle
and planting it in the printer garden.
[CACKLING]
What's so funny?
I mean, besides everything?
I have no intention
of returning this system.
On the contrary, I intend...
-to keep it.
-Dear God.
Delete.
COMPUTER:
One file selected.
Oh, hold on.
COMPUTER: File sorted.
-What? Oh, come on.
Come here, you little...
[PELTON GRUNTING]
[SHUSHING]
PELTON:
Don't fight it.
Just let go.
COMPUTER:
File deleted.
Jesus wept!
He deleted the serial number.
-Help me out here.
-I don't get paid enough for this.
How much do you think you'll get paid
if I have to find 5 grand in the budget?
You're not the new Annie.
-You're the new Abed.
-Don't know what that means yet.
[MAN SPEAKING PORTUGUESE
ON TV]
So are the gremlins supposed
to be the good guys in this version?
Blue ones are. Green ones are bad
and red ones are like isolationists.
-It's a metaphor for World War II.
-Ooh.
Um, I will be right back.
I left something in my car.
Oh.
Hi, yes.
I picked up a sofa
from your store recently.
The last name is Perry.
Mm-hm.
What?
-Are you strong or angry?
-My parents?
My parents bought that couch?
Explain yourself.
Well, are we--? Okay.
They kind of reached out to us
on Facebook.
What? You know I don't talk to them.
Well, yeah.
That's why they talked to us.
They knew you wouldn't let them
help you. Not directly.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
You needed our help,
but we needed their help to help you.
-That's why we got you a good deal.
-They're supplementing my rent too?
You make them sound like monsters
but they're actually really nice.
[GAGGING]
Well, they are.
My parents are horrible people.
-You're being dramatic.
-Oh, yeah.
That's what people say
when they take your soul
and they rip it out of your chest
and then shove it in your mouth!
I got bit by a cat.
[BOTH SCREAM]
PELTON:
Yes.
I will create more worlds here,
and those worlds will have worlds.
They're file folders.
Stop calling them "worlds."
I found an address.
Elroy Patashnik,
founder of VirtuGood Technologies.
I'll go see
if I can get the school's money back.
You keep white Morpheus
inside the Matrix.
[♪♪♪]
BRITTA: Jeff.
-Britta, you look distraught.
Ten seconds to tell me
it's not about stupid politics.
I found out Annie and Abed have
been cheating on me with my parents.
Sabotaging my life from the shadows by
paying off my debts, buying me things.
-Oh, thank God.
-What-- "Thank God"?
The charade can finally end.
Everything you thought you owed us,
you can just owe to Deb and George.
Deb and George?
You know my parents too?
Since when?
I don't know,
since thousands of dollars ago?
I'm bad with dates.
I remember the New Year's glasses
having zeros for eyes.
-When did Stella get her groove back?
-You've all been lying to me for years?
-What kind of friends are you?
-Poor.
We're poor friends.
You mooch off us because you're too
proud to use your own support system.
What kind of friend are you?
And having met them,
what were you rebelling against?
Was it generosity,
whimsical game nights,
or delicious lobster bacon
mashed potatoes?
You ate their potatoes?
You don't even eat carbs.
I eat love. Hot, delicious love that you
were willing to wipe your ass with.
Oh, my God.
-I have no friends.
-Can we not be so dramatic about this?
There are people in this world
with serious problems.
Chang, go see the nurse.
I'm trying.
[♪♪♪]
-Yeah?
-Elroy Patashnik?
-Who's asking?
-Well, that's always a yes.
Nobody says, "Who's asking?" to the wrong name.
They say, "That's not my name."
When my phone rings, I say, "Hello,"
they say, "Is Pablo there?"
I don't say, "Who's asking?"
I say, "Wrong number."
You're a clever young man.
-I'm 40.
-Come in.
So?
You sold a VirtuGood 6500
to Craig Pelton
at Greendale Community College,
and we need to return it.
I'll need the serial number.
He deleted the serial number
because he loves the system.
-What's the problem?
-Problem is, in order to copy a file,
you throw a fireball at it, then absorb the fire,
drop the flaming file into a crystal lake,
then throw them into the side of a mountain.
Worlds within worlds.
Doesn't mean anything. I can copy a file
by holding my finger down on a phone.
Oh, so can a monkey.
Now, you're describing a system
for animals.
Terrestrial slobs bound to the earth
by their meaty feet.
I designed a system for gods.
Oh, come on.
You know what you've done.
You know how lame virtual reality is.
You know the damage it caused
mid-'90s cinema.
Michael Douglas walking around
like a jackass,
moving files with a magic glove?
And Lawnmower Man--
Did you see Lawnmower Man?
You bet your sweet ass I saw
Lawnmower Man. I consulted on it.
Took Brigitte Nielsen to the premiere.
Building worlds within worlds.
Now you're living in homes
within campers within parking lots
and using an iPad to clearly design
what looks like a rip-off of "Angry Birds."
Get out. Get out of my Winnebago.
You're not allowed to say that
like it's a punishment.
I know what it's like to lie for a living, Elroy,
and you should know it feels better to stop.
And my feet aren't meaty.
-Britta, honey.
-An unexpected treat.
This is a check for all the dirty money
you've used to control and monitor me
without my consent.
-We're not gonna cash this.
-You can't. I postdated it a year.
And in that year,
I'm gonna get a new job, new friends,
in a new city where you and your spies
can never find me.
Oh, please, don't do this.
What choice do you leave me?
Who acts this dishonestly
towards their own daughter?
-What choice do you leave us?
-Yeah.
Every time we get too close,
you run off.
We sent you a birthday card
to your apartment,
the next week, you're setting fire
to a Jamba Juice in San Jose.
-How long is that gonna stick with me?
-Until arson is legal.
But your father's point is we've arrived at
the closest relationship you can tolerate.
We've learned after a decade
how to love and admire
and finance you from afar,
through your friends and the social media.
Tinder and the like.
It's called Tumblr, Dad.
No, I mean Tinder.
It's a matchmaking app.
And by the way,
if you were on Tinder, your mom and I
think you would be the prettiest.
Absolutely.
The boys would be swiping right.
GEORGE: Or girls.
-Yeah.
-Whatever makes you happy.
-Totally.
What has happened to you two?
Who are these doddering,
open-minded geezers?
Where are the people who wouldn't
let me dress up like Prince,
or told me that the cat ran away
because I tried alcohol,
or had me drug tested when I was 11
because they said I was laughing too much?
We are definitely sorry
about all of that stuff.
Quite frankly,
we don't remember that stuff.
DEB:
Well, it's true.
-Woodstock.
-Oh, my God.
I remember Woodstock!
-Woodstock was amazing.
-We had the--
-But you have to realize, Britta,
-Yep.
-that your Woodstock,
-Yeah.
which was us being bad parents,
that has more to do with you.
-So that's what you remember, see?
-Yeah. Mm-hm.
Where are they?
-I'm sorry.
-Get out here now!
Britta, let me explain.
We were worried about you,
so we just came over--
You can explain to each other in hell.
Friends don't visit
each other's parents.
I hope you have a wonderful life.
[CAR ENGINE SPUTTERING]
George, George, yes.
Britta, at least take some money
and fix your car.
Get a cab or there are apps we can call
where strangers pick you up.
I don't want your help!
Stop infantilizing me.
Hey, stop. Stop!
Get out of here.
Hey!
Green Machine. Nice.
Here, Greg. Here, take some cash.
Holy crap.
What's her problem?
She's growing up.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
Oh, my God.
I put a tilde on this N.
I can do anything!
[LAUGHING]
Any luck?
[GROANS]
I'm going home.
Oh, and to warn you,
he joked about wanting a pee jar earlier.
And it's gradually becoming
less of a joke.
Hey, Dean, I'm coming over,
and I'm pulling you out of there.
-I'll bite you.
-I'll beat you up.
I'll like it, I'll fire you,
I'll get right back in it.
-Well, still get to beat you up.
-Hold it. Hold it.
Who is that? I recognize that baritone voice
and scent of Tic Tacs
-with a tinge of Naugahyde.
-It's Elroy Patashnik.
[GASPS]
The Architect.
Listen, I've come to tell you something
very important about this system.
-It's lame.
-What?
I wasted your time with it
and 10 crucial years of America's time.
I'm giving Mr. Winger your refund.
I don't want a refund.
I wanna stay in here forever,
and you can't stop me.
Die!
Hyah, hyah, hyah!
How long has he been in there?
-Four hours?
-Oh.
-I was thinking weeks.
PELTON: Ha! Yup.
This guy runs your school?
Well...
To use a phrase I coined in the '90s,
"I'm going in."
-You coined that?
ELROY: Oh, yeah.
Lock and load.
-That's mine too.
-All right.
-I'm awake.
-Aah!
-Oh, my God!
-Oh, my god. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
-What are you doing in my car?
-I didn't have anywhere else to go.
Nowhere else but my car?
Do you know how big the planet is?
What is going on, Britta?
My friends, they all think
my parents are adorable.
They think I'm the bad guy
for hating them.
But I have a right.
I had to be there when they sucked.
Yeah, Jimmy Fallon Syndrome.
I get it.
I had that with my parents too.
-You did?
-Yeah.
You know, one of the most unfair lessons
we're forced to learn
is that our parents are human beings.
We wanna think of them as gods or demons,
because then that would make us heroes.
Ugh. Give me a break. We all suck.
[♪♪♪]
What can I do to help you tonight, Britta?
How many quarters
were in this cup holder?
The same amount.
ELROY:
Oh, yeah.
COMPUTER:
Calibrated. Welcome.
No. Go away.
COMPUTER:
Preferences. Grow.
[ELROY CACKLING]
No! No. No. Let go of me.
ELROY:
Do you really want the power of a god?
Yes, more than anything.
Should I order dinner? Because a lot
of good delivery places are closing.
I know how you feel. The sadder reality,
the less real we want it.
PELTON:
I just wanna be a good Dean.
ELROY: I can give you a device
that will accomplish that.
You can use this to manipulate worlds
with the flick of a wrist.
PELTON: My God, it's incredible.
ELROY: Now!
[SCREAMS]
What's happening?
No, I wanna go back in!
-I wanna be back in. Oh, I wanna be--
-Here, here, here. Here's your power.
Here. Now, manipulate worlds.
Yeah.
-He'll be back to his old self in an hour.
-Great.
Do you have a way to fix that?
[BOTH LAUGH]
♪ It's in the way that you use it ♪♪
[LAUGHING CONTINUES]
Seriously, thank you.
And... Ooh.
[DOOR OPENS]
Britta, we were so worried.
-What happened to the Green Machine?
-I don't know. I ditched it.
Where and how long ago?
Okay, I assume that's not what's important here.
Britta, we--
It's okay, Dad.
I have something that I wanna say.
I ran away from home at 17
to become an adult,
but maybe all that did
was leave a part of me stuck at 17,
the part that tends to run away
when I'm confronted with the truth.
The truth is good.
Mom, shut up.
Frankie taught me something important.
It doesn't matter how mature we are
or what resentments we carry.
All that matters
is that we're all going to die.
You have a lovely home.
-Thank you.
-We're really getting our daughter back?
It's not gonna be that big of a deal.
You missed the good years.
It's gonna be margaritas, Pottery Barn,
fighting our family's tendency
toward obesity as we slide into oblivion.
First you guys,
and then me quickly thereafter.
-Well, I'll drink to that.
-Oh, Britta.
Hi, Mom.
-Abed.
-Benjamin.
I got bit by a cat, Deb.
[ALL GASP]
I'll get the antibiotics.
Thank you for the refund, Elroy.
No, thank you...
for one last taste of what it was like
when my work was valuable.
Oh, it's still valuable.
Here, $500 for the taste I got
of being powerful.
-Dean, the school can't afford 500--
PELTON: Wait for it.
I have no idea what to do
with the rest of my life now.
We offer a wide variety of classes.
And that, my friend,
is the Greendale Effect.
-I'll never get out of here, will I?
-Ah.
I haven't met many that do. Heh.
Let's walk arm in arm.
PELTON: There are times
when change needs to be different.
Then there's changes
that are more the same.
But the same changes
don't tend to be different
than the changes that came before.
If you change everything that's different,
sometimes you find out...
You're back, Troy.
everything's still the same.
As for me, I'm just changing...
everything that's different.
Change.
[♪♪♪]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Chee-choo, chee-choo.
[IN PORTUGUESE]
[GREMLIN CACKLING]
[SCREAMING]
SHOP OWNER:
[IN PORTUGUESE]
[SCREAMS]
[GROWLS]
NARRATOR:
[♪♪♪]
[NARRATOR SPEAKING
IN PORTUGUESE]
[SCREAMS]
[♪♪♪]