[TICKING]
[ANNIE HUMMING]
[GASPS]
[BUZZING]
ANNIE [IN VOICEOVER]:
FRANKIE [IN VOICEOVER]:
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
PELTON [IN VOICEOVER]:
FRANKIE [IN VOICEOVER]:
ANNIE [IN VOICEOVER]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER IN JEFF'S VOICE]:
PELTON [IN VOICEOVER]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER]:
Hmm.
ANNIE [IN VOICEOVER]:
Oh, my God. How stupid can I get?
PELTON [IN VOICEOVER]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER]:
Brr.
Meow.
[TAKASHI LAUGHING]
PELTON: Meow.
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] Meow.
[SIGHS]
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up, tied up
Dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
Annie, if you're not dying,
I'm gonna murder you.
I had to remove my night cream.
It's $200 an ounce.
It's 3 a.m. in the freaking morning.
What gives you the right
to haul us in here?
Chang, how did you even
find out about this?
I have a right to be here.
Hi.
-Why are you so awake?
-I have a theory. Britta may be twins.
-No, I was working.
ANNIE: At the bar?
-Does that mean you're drunk?
-Uh, could a drunk person do this?
Hi, everybody.
Jeffrey.
Okay, 41 minutes ago,
I received this e-mail
-from a friend that interns at KZBC.
-The TV station?
No, the unrelated, totally random
combination of those four letters.
Mee-yow.
"Subject: Heads Up.
Annie, still going to Greendale?
Thought you should know
City College is running a negative ad
about your school at 7 a.m.
Heard it's pretty bad."
Let me see that.
City College is running an attack ad?
That's a first.
They're desperate.
Our registration numbers are trending upward.
Because the population keeps growing
and no one here ever graduates.
Actually, our numbers are up
because of improvements Frankie's made.
Those improvements were only possible
through your hard work, Annie.
-Get a boardroom.
-Interesting. When were you gonna
share the whole truth about this,
not just the parts that suit you?
-What?
-"P.S., I was glad
to hear Brenda's doing better"?
Huh? Huh?
[WHIMPERS]
Just because City College is scared
doesn't mean they're not dangerous.
Is there anything in particular
they could smear us with?
JEFF:
Nothing in particular,
just overlapping clouds of many
thousands and thousands of things.
-Don't forget the Brenda factor.
-There isn't a Brenda factor.
He says she's doing better.
Better than what?
Her thyroid condition. Can you focus?
-Can Brenda?
-Probably more so now.
-We need to see this ad before it airs.
-I'm getting a copy.
-I have friends in the City College AV Department.
-Ooh-la-la.
The brotherhood of AV exists
beyond your factionalism.
We serve only Video, the true queen,
and her consort, Audio.
Could you be bigger nerds?
No, we've achieved
our maximum potential.
Well, Annie's right.
We do have a situation here.
So we will make this our situation room.
Yes. We need white boards,
cork boards, laptops...
Clocks with different times,
a red phone,
a big map with tiny Nazi tanks,
and/or a Godzilla.
The ad airs at 7 a.m.
That means we have four hours
and 13 minutes to figure out
what they're throwing at us
and how to respond.
You know, it's the darndest thing.
I think Britta somehow crapped
in my pants too.
-Heh. I'd better head home.
-You can't just leave a situation room.
It's only a situation room
because she called it that.
I mean, I could declare it
a cookie room.
There are no cookies.
There is a situation.
You guys,
where's the Greendale spirit?
Where's the pride?
-I'm fine.
-Found it.
She was wandering around campus
without pants.
-What's going on here?
-Situation room.
-What's the situation?
-Brenda's thyroid.
Sorry to hear that. Keep the pants.
I'm going back to bed.
-I'm going with him.
-I'm gonna watch.
Got it. Downloading it now.
ANNOUNCER [OVER COMPUTER]:
You work hard to earn your degree.
And your school should work hard
to make that degree valuable.
So why is Greendale Community College
giving degrees to dogs?
In 2001,
a Staffordshire terrier named Ruffles
took up residence
on Greendale's campus.
By 2008, Ruffles had earned
a bachelor's degree.
Not a two-year degree,
a four-year degree.
Where will you get your degree?
If the answer is Greendale,
prepare to get boned.
Paid for by City College.
License 264392.
Did we give a degree to a dog?
-Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
-Ugh.
Okay. It's okay. It's all right.
[♪♪♪]
So this is Greendale,
not City College?
I'm gonna get more pants.
[♪♪♪]
They've been calling me in
to do more stuff. It's exciting.
We'll be lucky
if we get in three words--
The first step is to pool our facts.
The most important one being:
Dean Pelton,
did Greendale Community College
give a degree to a dog?
Oh. I seem to recall...
No. No way.
There's absolutely no way.
-Not that dog.
-"That dog"?
You remember the dog.
Was it enrolled in classes?
-Mm...
-How are these hard questions?
Why are these the questions
you're asking?
You don't wanna know
if a dog got a degree here?
It's not important.
What I wanna know is,
did a dog get a degree here
in any way that can be proven?
-Oh, I like that, Jeffrey.
-I don't like that. I like the truth.
Play lawyer on your own time.
This is my own time.
You wanted me invested?
Well, this dump cuts my paychecks,
and I've got three hours to defend it.
So how many seconds of that
should I waste on truth?
Which is an artificial construct
that rarely holds up in court,
and has never changed
the outcome of a fight.
-Sorry you have to see him like this.
-He's right.
If City College can't support their claim,
it's libel.
We can have the station pull the ad.
But that is precisely
why the truth does matter.
The Brenda Paradox.
I found the dog. I also found a lot
of Social Security numbers.
-This Internet has gone too far.
-Yeah.
-She's registered as a border terrier.
-They said Staffordshire.
JEFF:
Isn't that something?
We've known this animal 30 seconds
and she's already unreliable.
-Who is the real Ruffles?
FRANKIE: I'm sorry.
Our strategy is to go after the dog?
Our strategy is denial,
which includes discrediting the source.
Abed, can you make an attack ad?
Jeff wants me to make an attack ad.
So why is he a pedophile?
-Just demonstrating the formula.
-Refine your technique as you go.
I wanna know everything
about this Ruffles.
She thinks she went to this school, fine,
but maybe she thinks
cat turds are delicious.
And maybe she barks just
a little bit more at black mailmen.
And she's spayed now,
but how many puppies are out there?
You do this,
we're no better than City College.
We've never been better than City College.
We gave a degree to a dog.
Allegedly.
This conversation is privileged.
I could do a Banksy-style stencil
of a dog
-and spray-paint it all over the school.
-That sounds great.
First, why don't you go get
a bunch of coffee, drink all of it,
then go get some more
and bring it back here?
-I actually love that idea.
ELROY: I'll go with her.
She's wearing my pants.
I know this is crazy, but I'm gonna
go check the school records to see if,
you know, we gave a degree to a dog.
-We didn't.
JEFF: That's good.
You guys go find that truth
you love so much.
If it's the kind we can use,
bring it back.
If not, you know, stuff gets lost.
No. No. Bad.
We are better than City College.
We always have been.
Which is why I know
that we did not give a degree to a dog.
[ANNIE GROANS]
I say we fight fire with fire.
City College tries to embarrass us,
-we should embarrass them, right?
-Right.
I say I go to City College
with a camera,
shoot a really gross porno movie
on their campus and put it online.
-Fine.
-Cool.
Wait, what?
[SIGHS]
PELTON [IN VOICEOVER]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER IN JEFF'S VOICE]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER]:
[LAUGHING]
PELTON [IN VOICEOVER]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER]:
Honestly, I couldn't care less
if they gave a dog a degree.
Me neither. Ha-ha-ha.
In fact, I kind of hope they did.
-Why is that?
-I don't know.
They all treat me like I'm a joke.
But if a dog got a degree,
that means we're all a joke.
-Mm. Ha-ha-ha.
-Whoa.
Natalie is Freezing?
-You know them?
-Yeah, I know them.
But how do you? You're--
-Black?
-No. Old.
Oh. Sorry, I just meant that--
When I was into them, I was like 15.
And I was 40. I never really listened
to music when I was growing up.
I was in my own world.
But one day at work,
I heard this sound,
it was "Pillar of Garbage."
Oh, that is their best song. Best song.
-I got it right here.
-Would you play it?
Yeah.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
♪ Moonlight
Bleeding glass and healing needles ♪
♪ Amputated hearts are never whole ♪
♪ Too bright
Dreaming as the screaming seagulls ♪
♪ Feed on parts of me I keep below
Oh, oh ♪
♪ Orion, take off your belt
Let me go to where you've been ♪♪
[OFF-KEY] ♪ I'm flying, overhead
Buffalo are falling dead inside the-- ♪♪
[MUSIC STOPS]
You know what?
Those guys are gonna need coffee
if they're gonna keep that dog
from having a degree.
There are things at stake here.
I get that now. Mm.
I found the smell.
-Someone filed a taco.
-Wha--?
"Things That Will Otherwise Get Filed
Straight To My Thighs."
Hmm.
So I know you agree with me
that we need to find the truth,
but do you agree
that the truth won't be horrible?
I'm not psychic, Annie.
That's an illusion caused
by extreme preparedness.
But what do you hope is true?
Oh, God, no, I never hope.
Hope is pouting in advance.
Hope is faith's richer, bitchier sister.
Hope is the deformed, attic-bound,
incest monster offspring
of entitlement and fear.
My life results tripled when I gave up hope
and every game on my phone
that had to do with farming.
What's true will be true, Annie.
Our job is to deal with that truth.
You sound a little like Jeff.
Jeff said I sound like Abed.
I wonder if Britta thinks
I sound like Chang.
I assume Chang thinks I sound like
distant explosions and crying babies.
You know he's unstable, right?
-Yep.
-Oh.
A transcript for Ruffles.
-You think that's our guy?
-I do.
Oh, my God.
So many classes.
[♪♪♪]
See what hope does?
Screw you, Frankie.
I'm sorry, Annie, but I don't think
you're seeing this for what it is.
It's a transcript for a dog.
A really, really long one.
It's proof that Jeff was right.
This school has no value.
Yeah. But this folder has no degree.
Look.
-What's that?
-Heh-heh-heh.
Victory.
You know,
within the context of Greendale.
-Would it be better if we--?
-No.
Never know until you try.
-Never know until I try.
-What?
-I said we're quite a team.
-Here's the coffee.
Let me know
if there's anything else I can do.
-We could use fresh eyes on this cut.
-We could?
-Has anyone told you you're difficult?
-Everyone in your line of work.
[MUSIC PLAYS OVER COMPUTER]
ANNOUNCER:
This is Ruffles.
She'd like you to believe
she's a graduate and a good girl.
But Ruffles is anything but.
When Ruffles moved
into her neighborhood in 2007,
dead squirrels went up
by 17 percent.
Coincidence? Ask this bunny.
Ruffles stole cookies from a Girl Scout,
impersonated a lobster,
has had 27 children
with five different fathers,
and according to one local doctor,
has worms.
Ruffles might claim she doesn't.
Ruffles claims a lot of things.
Maybe that's why Ruffles
once spent time on death row.
Ruffles: not a lobster, not a student,
not a good dog.
Paid for by Humanity Versus Ruffles.
I wanted the voice-over
to be like James Earl Jones,
but the James Spader impersonator
turned out pretty good.
I wish he'd leave, though.
-You really let that dog have it.
-Yeah.
Which I realize is important now.
Is it okay if I crash on--?
-Yes.
-What are you doing?
-Nothing at all.
I wouldn't say that. You put
five huge cans of olives next to me.
Just something I felt like doing.
This isn't the first time
you've done this.
I'm really confused by this.
-Is it code for something?
-I don't know.
And I don't care.
[PELTON CHUCKLES]
Jackpot, relative to Greendale.
Oh, my God. Look at this course load.
This dog was an animal.
-Most of them were attendance-based.
-How is this good news?
"Unpaid library fees, $15.
Diploma withheld
until payment remitted."
No degree. The commercial's a lie.
FRANKIE: I'm gonna call the station
and have them pull the ad.
Eat crap, Ruffles,
and not just your own.
-Guys. Let it go.
-What are you talking about?
The sad truth is that
a dog can get a degree here.
Yeah, but the happy truth is none did.
There's a difference between truth
and honesty.
Library dues? Who cares?
Ruffles put the work in,
relative to Greendale.
That City College ad
may be technically a lie,
but it's really dishonest
to kill it on a technicality.
And dragging this dog's name
through the mud?
That's worse than dishonest.
That's evil.
Evil? I'll cop to silly.
Some things are silly and evil,
like candy cigarettes.
And remember when Flavor Flav
had that reality show?
I don't own a TV.
Honestly, I think the most honest thing
we can do right now,
the only thing that will make us
better than City College,
is to let that ad run and take our lumps.
Annie, this started with me sleeping
and getting yelled at for not helping.
If it ends with you yelling at me
for not sleeping, that's not a story,
that's a German art film.
What--? Let it go.
I am a female student being physically
overpowered by a male teacher!
Damn it. Britta, get her.
[SNORING]
-Frankie, get her.
-Annie, sweetie,
think about this practically.
If being better than City College
means letting them destroy us,
what is the point?
If surviving means being like them,
what's the point?
Why not let one school die
and enroll at the one
where my grades matter?
[♪♪♪]
If those are your terms...
If the price of that transcript
is you transferring...
[SCOFFS]
we accept.
Personally, I hope you're bluffing.
Yeah? Well, here's what hope gets you.
Hope and a dollar forty-nine
will get you a candy bar.
-A buck seventy-nine.
-Are you serious? Jesus.
Have fun with your lying, cheating,
dog-smearing, truth-blurring,
trouser-swapping school!
ELROY: I remember
when candy bars were 50 cents.
If someone says,
"Hey, I just joined Mensa"
or, "I consider myself
a post-modern this or that."
You could say, "Yeah, that and 50 cents
will get you a candy bar."
Or, "That and a quarter
will get you a phone call." Heh.
It was easier
to be unimpressed back then.
I mean, it was literally cheaper.
Elroy, we're kind of bummed out
right now.
-Annie just left.
ELROY: Oh.
Were you guys close?
[♪♪♪]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
-Abed, I don't wanna talk right now.
-Okay.
The Greendale ad is gonna go up
any time now. You might wanna see it.
-I don't wanna be a part of that.
-Trust me.
This is Ruffles.
Ruffles was a student at
Greendale Community College.
She came really close
to getting a degree.
Which means two things.
She's an exceptional dog,
and Greendale really needs
to get its **** together.
We're working on it. We're working hard.
And the good news is,
when you work hard at Greendale,
no matter who or what you are,
it pays off. Right, Ruffles?
[BARKS]
Jesus.
ANNOUNCER:
Greendale Community College.
You're already accepted.
You guys.
I knew you wouldn't do that to Ruffles.
-You hoped.
-I hoped and it worked.
-Hope points.
You do understand that what we did
was the most prudent tactical move?
Getting in front of the scandal,
Letterman style.
Yes, Jeff, don't worry.
I promise I'll never mistake you
for having a heart.
-Thank you.
-Ahem. Kiss City College goodbye.
-I did it.
-Did what?
That stuff we talked about.
CHANG [IN HIGH VOICE]: Who are you?
CHANG [IN NORMAL VOICE]: I'm the plumber.
CHANG [IN HIGH VOICE]: Why?
CHANG [IN NORMAL VOICE]: Here's why.
-Oh.
-Oh, my God. Oh, my--
ELROY: Oh!
-Ugh.
[CHANG MOANING ON VIDEO]
-Is this pornography?
-Doy.
-You're the only actor.
-So?
-What kind of lens is this?
-Who cares?
You might be a genius.
Why did you do this?
What parent will let their kid go to this school
if a porn got shot there?
You shot it in front of a wall
that could be anywhere.
And you're wearing
your Greendale T-shirt.
Okay, genius,
but the title is Chang Does Greendale--
Oh, wait.
[CHUCKLES]
Reshoots.
[IN JAPANESE]
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
[CELL PHONE BUZZES]
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER IN ENGLISH]:
PELTON [IN VOICEOVER]:
TAKASHI [IN VOICEOVER]:
[♪♪♪]
OLDER TAKASHI:
I often think about that night.
Such a small event,
but ultimately,
the moment that would lead me
to becoming oyabun,
highest leader of the Yakuza.
[♪♪♪]