"Always scare, Daniel-san.
Miyagi hate fighting."
Miyagi hate fighting.
-Line?
-"Yeah, but you like karate."
Right, right.
Yeah, but you like karate, though.
"So...?"
-Line?
-Chang, the audition's at 3.
Well, maybe I shouldn't go.
Maybe I'm a bad actor.
Being good is a fraction of acting.
It takes discipline and confidence.
Discipline. Confidence.
Okay, from the top.
"Always scare, Daniel-san.
Miyagi hate fighting."
Line.
I heard Karate Kid quotes?
Chang is auditioning for a stage adaptation
of Karate Kid downtown.
Yeah, and it's for the part
of Daniel LaRusso.
-You got a problem with that, racist?
-No. You're acting now?
Yeah. Um, you got a problem with that?
I'm clear.
ELROY: They took my snake
and they turned it into a plumber.
They made the eggs into barrels,
the pine tree into a gorilla,
but I recognize my design.
"Donkey Kong," my ass.
That's "Construction Snake."
I don't practice law anymore.
-But we have a case, right?
-Isn't everyone you'd be suing dead?
That's not cool, man.
Why would a tree throw eggs
at a snake?
-Why would a plumber fight a monkey?
-I don't know. I don't know.
-The Wi-Fi is broken.
-What happened to "Good morning"?
-It's a bad morning. No Wi-Fi.
-Yeah, we need Wi-Fi.
Okay, let's not get carried away.
We need oxygen.
We have oxygen. We need Wi-Fi.
ALL:
Wi-Fi. Wi-Fi.
Wi-Fi. Wi-Fi!
Okay, enough. All right?
Look what I'm doing. Look.
"Fix Wi-Fi."
Okay? Boom and boom.
All right,
I am trying to find the IT lady.
My e-mails to her
get bounced back to me in Aramaic.
And when I call, I hear
an undulating high-pitched whistle
-that makes my nose bleed.
-Well, sounds like a bad IT lady, right?
-Frankie, hire a new IT lady.
-I'm handy with technology.
I'm assuming it's the same.
Smaller holes, more bytes?
-What are we up to now, mega?
-Tera.
Tera.
They did it, those bastards.
They finally did it.
-Hire Elroy. Elroy, you're the IT lady.
-Can I be his assistant?
-Not for money.
-Can I be his friend?
Elroy, Abed is your friend.
Now, the real reason I came by.
I'm dying.
[ALL GASP]
Not really,
but imagine how bad you'd feel
for complaining about the Wi-Fi.
Here's the real reason.
Too short?
It is too short?
It's not too short?
Ugh, you people are no help.
[THE 88'S "AT LEAST IT WAS HERE" PLAYING]
♪ Give me some rope
Tie me to dream ♪
♪ Give me the hope
To run out of steam ♪
♪ Somebody said
It can be here ♪
♪ We could be roped up, tied up
Dead in a year ♪
♪ I can't count the reasons
I should stay ♪
♪ One by one
They all just fade away ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
-School board coming.
-Oh, God.
-School board, you're surrounded.
-If this is about the bonfire,
-we'll put it out when the weather breaks.
-We come in peace.
We've had our ups and downs,
but as of right now, we love the school.
-And love what you're doing with it.
-What? Why?
What would you think
about moving up?
-You know, joining us on the board.
-Me?
-I would love to.
-Awesome.
RICHIE: One more thing.
You're, uh, gay, right?
I mean, like, openly gay?
Uh, I'm not openly anything,
and gay doesn't begin to cover it, no.
Oh.
Oh, I get it. This is about the uproar
over you guys canceling
the pride parade
for a school-board parade.
-Those guys get to dress fancy all year.
-No, no, no.
-We have one day!
-No, this isn't about that.
This is about adding a new face
to the board.
But if that new face happened to be openly gay,
it would be because we're so tolerant.
And always were.
But that's for us to deal with.
The question you have to ask is:
"Am I openly gay?"
Because if you are,
that gayness could be a rocket.
Thrusting you to new gay heights.
And if you're not, well,
there's a lot of gay guys out there.
I assume that's a selling point
of the lifestyle.
-I never thought about it that way.
-Well, I have.
Cutting women out of sex?
It's genius.
♪ Gay Dean, Gay Dean, Gay Dean ♪
♪ Gay Dean ♪
♪ I'm begging you to be a gay dean
Of the school board ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
This should lead to the router.
[BIRDS TWITTERING]
-Back up, back up, back up.
-What--? What's going on?
A bird's nest, with babies.
It must be there because of the heat.
Reason my mom took
my half-brother to Arizona.
That's why the Wi-Fi is down.
We'll have to move it.
If you move them,
the mother won't come back.
Those birds aren't the new IT lady.
I am.
-I'll move it carefully.
-The mother won't come back.
Kid, animals have been murdering
each other for 3 billion years.
Birds have had their 15 million
in the spotlight, same as lizards and plants.
And they all just use it to murder,
eat, screw and not invent Wi-Fi.
We may end up saving this world,
or blowing it to hell,
or making a new one.
But we can't do any of it
while scheduling our evolution
around the needs
of the least lucky birds.
Are you a demon?
Did Clive Barker write you?
Anyone who finds that nest
will come to the same decision.
And you don't have to get mean.
Mean? You just did
a baby-bird murder monologue.
Maybe they're close to leaving.
Can you stall by doing what real IT people do?
-What's that?
-Exactly.
[♪♪♪]
I've got one year to make it all work,
and that's what I'm gonna do.
Make it work. All of it.
This place is intimidating.
You're gonna do great.
Next up, Ben Chang
for the role of Daniel LaRusso.
Ah. Thank you.
Daniel-san,
why you want learn karate?
Hang on a second.
-Sorry, I can do better.
-Zip it.
-Who are you?
-Oh, I'm Annie, a friend of Chang's.
You mind coming up here
and reading with your friend?
Okay. If it helps.
Um...
"Daniel-San, why you want--?"
MATT:
Okay. No, sorry. No.
You read Daniel-San.
You read Miyagi.
Um...
MATT:
We'll do scene seven, Miyagi's office.
Ahem.
[IN NEW JERSEY ACCENT]
Are you the repairman?
CHANG:
Aye.
ANNIE: The faucet's really leaky there.
CHANG: Aye.
When you gonna fix it?
After.
Heh. After what?
"After" after.
Tell everyone else to go home.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
We got the parts!
ABED: Yeah.
ELROY: Hear, hear.
Parts, plural?
Well, yeah, Annie got my part,
and I got the Asian part.
ANNIE:
Chang, stop.
We were cast as Mr. Miyagi
and the Karate Kid
because we're a good team.
We're a team
because one of us is so talented,
she got cast outside her gender,
and the other one got cast
because of eye shape.
I am not letting you
sabotage yourself like this.
Let's say you're right,
and like Sidney Poitier
or Meg Ryan before you,
you were cast for race.
It's what the actor does with the role
they get that matters. All right?
You're right.
All right, IT lady, how goes it?
-I found your problem.
-And...?
I'll need a little time to fix it.
Wow, need time to fix it.
You sound just like you work in IT.
I've got some interesting news.
The school board offered me a position.
-Great.
-Congratulations.
Well, I got a part in a play,
and we were sort of talking about that,
so read the room, Pelton.
BRITTA:
Are you gonna take the job?
I don't know. There's a catch. Heh-heh.
Jeffrey, Frankie,
could I see you in my office, please?
They want you to be
a token homosexual?
It's a form of progress.
Thirty years ago, the most power
the openly gay could achieve
was the center square.
But I'm not just gay.
What does that mean?
If coming out is a magic show,
and gayness is a rabbit out of a hat,
I'm one of those
never-ending handkerchiefs.
The sad truth, Craig?
Anything other than straight
is plenty gay for a school board.
The most important point is,
are you prepared
to make your sexuality--
Which is nobody's business.
--an aspect of your role in society?
I know I'm not, so I don't.
PELTON &amp; JEFF:
Oh?
When a person becomes symbolic,
-they gain symbolic power
-[MOUTHING] Gay?
-at the price of independent power.
-Maybe?
Yep, that's an excellent point.
It could be good for Greendale
for one of our own
to be on the school board.
The fact you'd be leaving
a few items off your list of turn-ons...
I mean, the goal in politics
isn't transparency, it's winning.
That's why politicians always win.
They do always win, don't they?
Now I get a chance to win.
I could change the system
from the inside out.
And all I have to do
is pare down my sexuality
to simple gayness,
which is heavily in the mix.
There you go.
Get ready, America.
Dean Pelton is coming out
as approximately two-sevenths
of what he is. Heh-heh.
Come on. Don't leave me hanging.
There we go.
-I am so curious.
-Oh!
-Intellectually.
-Oh, Jeffrey.
All right, this is a pretty basic scene.
No real subtext.
Let's just get it up on its feet.
There's no wrong answers.
Okay? Great. Go.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Hey, come fix faucet.
[SCOFFS]
-Oh! Karate. Learn from book?
-[IN NEW JERSEY ACCENT] Yeah.
And a few classes back at the Y
in Jersey, where I'm from.
-What happened eye?
-Okay, I'm gonna stop you right there.
I guess there are wrong answers.
-Quick adjustment, Ben?
CHANG [IN NORMAL VOICE]: Yeah?
Act better. Act better. Thanks.
Annie, you're doing great.
-Keep doing what you're doing.
-Can I ask about my moti--?
To keep me from puking
is your motivation.
Stop making me wanna quit theater
and kill myself. Go.
After "what happen eye?"
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Oh. Okay.
[IN NEW JERSEY ACCENT]
Hey, I fell off my bike.
Mm.
-[IN DEEP VOICE] Lucky no hurt hand.
-Okay.
Can I see this toolbox?
Ah. Great. This is good. Got it.
Ah!
I got distracted because the tools
were doing a better job than you.
"What happen eye?" Say it!
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] What happen eye?
-Liar.
Stop lying to me. Say it.
-What happen eye?
-What happen actor?
[SNIFFLING]
Are you crying?
You cry when I tell you to cry.
So reabsorb that disgusting droplet
of salt and bad choices
back into your doughy body.
Then call your mother to see
if you can be reabsorbed
back into her doughy body.
Or I will take that tear, I'll freeze it
and stab you in the eye with it,
you waste of a soul-shaped hole
forgotten by God.
[SOBS]
Okay.
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] What should I--?
-Don't change a thing. You're perfect.
Unless you want to.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
All right. I'm Rich Countee.
This is my man, Carl.
-We work on the school board.
-Yeah, we do.
We have some exciting news for you.
Your own Dean Craig Pelton
has been selected to join the board
of Colorado Community Colleges.
-I'll just-- Go-- Go ahead, Dean. Talk.
MAN: Yeah.
PELTON:
Hello, Greendale.
As you know, this is something
I've wanted for a very long time.
I wanted to thank all the people
at Greendale that helped me achieve this.
And my partner, Domingo.
-Very proud of my Craig.
-Aw, that's--
Oh! Ha-ha-ha.
And now let's open it up
to some questions.
As a gay dean, what is your opinion
about the recent controversy
surrounding the canceled pride parade?
Do you think you were selected
to join the board
because of your sexual preferences?
Whoa, I would just like to say
that we are very proud
to have Mr. Pelton on the board,
whatever his lifestyle may be.
Which happens to be gay.
Which is great, but irrelevant.
It gets better.
[LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY]
Oh... Oh, good.
We're so happy. Ha-ha-ha.
-I feel like scum.
-Gay people are scum?
Don't play that card with me.
I make gayness look like Mormonism.
I don't like being this dishonest.
Dean, I wanna say thanks
for doing this.
I never knew. I mean, people talked,
but I wasn't sure.
It doesn't have anything
to do with my work--
Yeah, but it's helpful to me, you know?
And to a lot of us. So thank you.
Hmm...
Confine yourself to your role,
Domingo.
And lose the attitude.
♪ Gay Dean, Gay Dean
Gay Dean, Gay Dean ♪
♪ I'm begging you to be a gay dean
For the school board ♪
♪ Your lifestyle is alternative
Your influence is positive ♪
♪ You're everything
The changing of the tide ♪
♪ Gay Dean
Gay Dean ♪♪
♪ Hare Krishna, Krishna, Krishna ♪♪
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Oh, Daniel-San, you much humor.
Okay, let's stop there.
[MATT SIGHS]
I'm not gonna hit you
and it's not because it's illegal.
And it's not because I'm afraid
you know karate,
because there is nothing about
your performance that is believable.
See, we only hit things
that affect us.
I don't hit water or old mayonnaise
or the air after a fart has dissipated,
and I'm not hitting you.
You are the worst actor I've ever directed,
and I directed both Wahlbergs!
From the top!
Danny does a bit with the floor sanders,
Miyagi is amused,
and Kenny gets me another goddamn
cup of coffee with six Splendas in it.
♪ Hare Krishna ♪♪
He's so mean to Chang.
I don't know what to do.
You could just drop out of the play.
Well, you know, I could.
Or Chang could.
I mean, the director's
not being mean to me.
But you talked Chang
into auditioning,
and then you got his part
and now he's suffering.
-You're right. I should threaten to quit.
-Or just quit.
Well, if I threaten to quit,
maybe that will be enough for him
to stop abusing Chang.
I was kind of born to act, Britta.
When I do it,
I can feel it pleasing the universe.
That's dramatic.
See?
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[♪♪♪]
If they're sparrows,
they'll fly in less than 12 days.
If they're albatrosses,
we're in trouble.
Albatrosses have
a 270-day fledging period.
Thanks for guarding the nest with me.
Uh-oh.
This is what you do when you're working?
-Must be nice.
-All right, look.
There's a bird's nest in the router.
If you wanna fire me, fire me.
Either way, until those birds are gone,
nobody gets any closer.
Well, of course not. If you move them,
the mother won't come back.
Keep up the good work.
Hm.
[♪♪♪]
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Show me wax on.
This is the worst acting
I've ever seen in my life.
Show me wax off.
The ghost of your father
just turned his back on you.
Your ancestors are clawing their way
deeper into the earth to get away from you.
You make me embarrassed
to have thumbs.
I can see air quotes around you.
Show me paint fence.
Knock, knock. Anybody home?
Oh, look, there's nobody here.
Oh, it's so dusty.
It's almost like nobody's been here in years.
There's a note.
"Never let me act!"
Mr. Lundergard, I'm sorry,
but I cannot stand by while you do this.
That's fine. You can go.
I'm not bluffing.
You can't make an actor more talented
by yelling at them.
And if you don't stop,
your lead character is gonna walk.
Lead?
You play Danny LaRusso.
Well, I'm the Karate Kid.
The Karate Kid is about Kesuke Miyagi,
an immigrant who fought
his own people in World War II
while his wife lost a child
in an internment camp.
Noriyuki Morita was nominated for
an Academy Award for his performance.
Ralph Macchio showed up.
I cast you because your measurements
allow me to use the wardrobe from last year.
I cast Ben because he has
the sadness and talent
that could make this show great,
if I have to physically drill into his chest
and suck it out with a straw!
So you can take a flying kick
at a rolling doughnut.
You're fired.
But I'm talented too, right?
What? No. Really?
Really? Oh, my God.
You're, like, doing a terrible
Vinnie Barbarino up here.
I know you're not capable of anything better,
so that's why I've been so nice to you.
Take care, Annie.
Yikes, right? Whew!
What a diva.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Thanks for sticking up for me.
No problem?
From now on, she's dead to us.
Hey, Gay Dean, we got a problem here.
You reading the local papers?
You've shut down the campus Wi-Fi
until a nest of baby birds can grow?
-That's a little too gay.
-I didn't do it because I'm gay.
Wait, I'm not gay.
Whoa, that did not just get said to us.
You're gay. You're openly gay, and we love it.
We're dealing with more flak from conservatives
for appointing you
than we did from gays
for not having one of you.
Yeah, and the gays aren't coming to your side.
Know why? Because the whole point
is to get a job by being gay,
and then to do as good a job as the normals.
That's what the gays want.
They don't want a gay dean
who acts like a weird gay monster.
-I'm not a gay dean.
-Whoa, not cool, man.
-Don't bring us into your web of lies.
-Well...
-Now what do you want me to do?
RICHIE: Figure it out, Gay Dean.
Figure it out.
-Hey, Domingo.
-Hey, what's up?
[SIGHS]
Guys, the school needs Wi-Fi,
and my job is to run the school.
The school doesn't need baby birds.
-The nest needs to be moved.
-You are not crossing this line.
I'm taping this. This is on video.
-Guys.
-This is two white security guards
versus one unarmed black man
and two baby birds.
Your move.
Stand down. Stand down.
No security, no weapons,
just one unarmed black man
versus one unarmed, openly gay dean.
Now, move that nest, please.
Just a hair back, Domingo.
It's like you're breathing for me.
♪ Your lifestyle is alternative
Your influence is positive ♪
♪ You represent
The changing of the tide ♪
♪ Inspiring to young gay men
You'll never be ashamed again ♪
♪ But there's another secret
Locked inside ♪
♪ Gay Dean, Gay Dean, Gay Dean ♪
♪ Gay Dean ♪
♪ I'm begging you to be a gay dean
For the school board ♪
♪ Gay Dean, Gay Dean, Gay Dead
Gay Dean ♪♪
Thank you so much.
You are an inspiration.
[♪♪♪]
[ALL CHATTERING]
[ALL SHUSHING]
Ahem.
I've called this press conference
because I have been
less than honest with the public.
You know me as the openly gay dean
of Greendale Community College,
but that doesn't even begin
to describe what I really am.
I belong to one
of the most marginalized
and least openly honest groups
in America.
I am...
a politician.
Now, what does that mean?
Are politicians like you?
Well, we look like you.
But we will say and do
whatever we have to
in order to acquire
and keep our jobs.
It means nothing I say
and very few of the things I think
can be trusted.
[♪♪♪]
I am tired of being
in this particular closet,
so I am coming out now.
I only hope that you can accept
an openly political person
on your board.
If not...
I understand.
Thank you.
[ALL CLAMORING]
It's faster if I get to my office this way.
We don't need pictures of this.
I can't believe he got kicked off
the school board
for admitting he's political.
Yeah, some groups take longer
than others to gain acceptance.
We like our politicians in the closet
because we're afraid, deep down,
-we're all a little political.
-Any of you smell a bird murderer?
I came here to apologize.
I hope your apology comes
with a beak, hollow bones,
and a special magnet in its head
it uses to migrate.
-You skipped wings.
-Insects have wings!
-I'm sorry.
PELTON: I'm sorry, Abed.
I lost myself in a role.
It won't happen again.
Two of them died. There's one left.
He's hanging on,
but I'm worried he's turning
into a symbol of my own innocence.
Oh...
-Isn't Chang's play tonight?
-If you go, you're supporting abuse.
-Oh, dial it back, Annie.
-Oh!
I'm definitely in. It'll be interesting
to see how his fake crying
-is different from his real crying.
-I'm a big fan of the performing arts.
But I'll go to Chang's play anyway.
Karate Kid adaptation?
Karate Kid adaptation? Karate Kid adaptation?
[♪♪♪]
Ahem.
Karate Kid adaptation?
Okay. Ah! I might.
I'm catching up.
[CROWD MURMURING]
MATT:
Directors have a saying.
Actors are worthless,
empty-headed homunculi.
But the right one in the right role
can change the world. Hm.
I have found the right one.
He's found the right role.
And tonight, your world changes.
You're welcome.
[♪♪♪]
-He replaced me with Annie Kim?
-Shh.
-Hyah!
TONY: Ow!
Sorry. You okay?
You must be the new people
in Apartment 20.
What was that, karate?
KIM: Yeah, you know.
-[MOUTHS] Yeah, you know.
Hey, me and my friends are gonna
have a party at the beach.
You should come.
-Hey, are you the repairman?
CHANG [IN DEEP VOICE]: Aye.
KIM:
Faucet's really leaking there.
-Aye.
-When are you gonna fix it?
After.
After what?
"After" after.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Come ask leave boy alone to train.
You got a lot of nerve, old man.
But I like that. I like that.
Name a place.
CHANG:
Tournament.
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHING]
Sergeant Miyagi. Yes, sir.
Regret to inform wife, sir.
Complication at birth, sir.
[SNIFFLING]
No doctor in camp.
Why she d--?
[CHANG SOBBING]
-Please forgive me.
-Shh.
No need fight anymore.
You proved point.
What, that I could take a beating?
Every time I see those guys,
they'll know they got the best of me.
Close eye.
[RUMBLING AND AUDIENCE GASPS]
Get up, Daniel.
Get up.
[♪♪♪]
[YELLS]
[CHEERING]
Yeah!
Yeah, woot, woot! Ha-ha!
You're all right, LaRusso.
KIM:
We did it, Mr. Miyagi.
We did it.
-I'm speechless.
-I forgot Chang was up there.
BRITTA:
Me too. It's such a relief
to be able to support him
out of something other than fear.
Guess all that suffering paid off.
You have to wonder
if it wouldn't have been better
for Daniel to get beat up even more.
I am at a total loss about
what lesson to learn from any of this.
Maybe that's the lesson.
Mmm...
-I lost a button.
-Maybe we all lost a button.
CHANG [IN NORMAL VOICE]:
Hey. Hey, guys.
[ALL CHEERING]
Thank you so much.
-Hey. Thank you for making me do this.
-You're welcome. Congratulations.
-I'm jealous.
-Oh, no, no. Don't be.
I sit in my dressing room,
and all I dream about
is a white picket fence and the dog.
I don't have those either.
[MATT WHISTLES]
Chang, let's go.
I guess all the actors go to some sort of
actor bar together, heh-heh.
I'll see you guys in school. Bye.
[♪♪♪]
MATT:
What are you talking to them for?
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
Hey, I know this great bar for people
that don't hate themselves.
What do you say?
Milady.
Milord. Ha!
We're gathered here today
to celebrate the release
of this bird into these skies.
That its now fully formed wings
may find purchase upon the four winds.
If anyone would like to say something,
now is the time.
Oh. Uh...
I'll always remember how you kept me
from getting e-mail for a week.
And that chirp you do
when you want more bread.
[BIRD CHIRPS]
Yeah, that one.
Now, everyone, please put on
your cat masks and finger wings.
With these cat masks, we remind you
that this place can no longer be home.
But with the fluttering of these wings,
we symbolically join your flight
into the natural world. Wings, everyone.
Okay, you can go now.
Off you go.
Time to go, little bird.
That's just the way it is.
[ALL CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
-It's done.
BRITTA: You did the right thing.
Thanks to you, that bird has
his whole life ahead of him.
To fly, meet lady birds, even start
a bird family. You made a difference.
Oh, Abed.
[♪♪♪]
[CHIRPING]