Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41153.7:
Our destination is
planet Deneb IV
beyond which lies the great,
unexplored mass of the galaxy.
My orders are
to examine Farpoint,
a starbase built there by
the inhabitants of that world.
Meanwhile, I am becoming
better acquainted
with my new command
this Galaxy-class
USS Enterprise.
I am still somewhat in awe
of its size and complexity.
As for my crew,
we are short
in several key positions
most notably,
a first officer,
but I am informed that
a highly experienced man--
one Commander
William Riker--
will be waiting
to join the ship
at our Deneb IV destination.
You will agree, Data,
that Starfleet's orders
are difficult.
Difficult?
Simply solve the mystery
of Farpoint Station.
As simple as that.
Farpoint Station--
even the name
sounds mysterious.
It's hardly simple,
Data, to negotiate
a friendly agreement
for Starfleet to use the base
while at the same time
snoop around,
finding out how and why
the life-form there built it.
Inquiry--
the word... "snoop"?
Data, how can you
be programmed
as a virtual encyclopedia
of human information
without knowing
a simple word like snoop?
A possibility--
a kind of human behavior
I was not designed to emulate.
It means, uh...
to, uh...
spy, to sneak.
Ah! To seek covertly, to go
stealthily, to slink, slither...
Exactly, yes.
Glide, creep, skulk,
pussyfoot, gum...
Yes.
...shoe.
Captain...
I'm sensing a...
a powerful mind.
( alarm blaring )
Something strange on
this detector circuit.
( electrical crackling )
DATA:
It registers as solid, Captain.
Or an incredibly
powerful force field
but if we collide with either,
it could be very...
Shut off that damn noise!
Go to yellow alert!
( alarm stops )
Shields and deflectors up, sir.
( electrical crackling )
Reverse power-- full stop!
Controls at full stop, sir.
Now reading full stop, sir.
Thou art notified
that thy kind
hath infiltrated the galaxy
too far already.
Thou art directed to return
to thine own solar system
immediately.
That's quite a directive.
Would you mind identifying
what you are?
We call ourselves the "Q."
Or thou mayest call me that.
It's all much the same thing.
I present myself to thee
as a fellow ship captain
that thou mayest
better understand me.
Go back whence
thou camest.
Stay where thou art.
Data, call medics.
He's frozen!
He would not have injured you.
Do you recognize this--
the stun setting?
Knowing humans
as thou dost, Captain,
wouldst thou be
captured helpless by them?
Now, go back,
or thou shalt
most certainly die.
Captain's Log,
supplementary:
The frozen form
of Lieutenant Torres
has been rushed to Sick Bay.
The question now
is the incredible power
of the Q being.
Do we dare oppose it?
Captain,
thy little centuries
go by so rapidly.
Perhaps thou will
better understand this.
Actually, the issue
at stake is patriotism.
You must return to your world
and put an end to the Commies.
All it takes are
a few good men.
What?
That nonsense
is centuries behind us.
But you can't deny
that you're still a dangerous,
savage child race.
Most certainly I deny it.
I agree we still were
when humans wore costumes
like that 400 years ago.
At which time,
you slaughtered millions
in silly arguments
about how to divide
the resources
of your little world.
And 400 years before that,
you were murdering each other
in quarrels
over tribal god images.
Since then,
there are no indications
that humans will ever change.
But even when we wore
costumes like that
we'd already started
to make rapid progress.
Oh, yeah? Do you want
to review your rapid progress?
Rapid progress--
where humans learned to control
their military with drugs.
Sir, Sick Bay reports
Lieutenant Torres'
condition is better.
Oh, concern for one's
fellow comrade.
How touching.
And now,
a personal request, sir.
Permission to clean up
the Bridge.
Lieutenant Worf is right, sir.
As security chief, I can't
just stand here and let...
Yes, you can,
Lieutenant Yar.
Oh, better.
Then later, on finally
reaching deep space,
humans of course found enemies
to fight out there, too.
And to broaden
those struggles,
you again found allies
for still more murdering.
The same old story
all over again.
No. The same old story
is the one we're meeting now--
self-righteous life-forms
who are eager not to learn,
but to prosecute to judge
anything they don't understand
or can't tolerate.
What an interesting idea.
Prosecute and judge.
Suppose it turns out
we understand you humans
only too well.
We've no fear of what the true
facts about us will reveal.
Facts about you?
Splendid, splendid, Captain.
You're a veritable fountain
of good ideas.
There are preparations to make,
but when we next meet, Captain,
we'll proceed
exactly as you suggest.
Sir, respectfully submit
our only choice is to fight.
Fight or try
to escape.
Sense anything, Commander?
Its mind is
much too powerful.
Recommend
we avoid contact.
From this point,
no station aboard--
repeat-- no station
for any reason
will make use of transmitted
signals or intercom.
We'll try and take them
by surprise.
Let's see what this
Galaxy-class starship can do.
Lieutenant, inform
Engine Room to prepare for
maximum acceleration.
Aye, sir.
Records search, Data.
Results of detaching saucer
section at high warp velocity.
Inadvisable at
any warp speed, sir.
Search theoretical.
It is possible,
but absolutely
no margin for error.
Using printout only,
notify all decks
to prepare for maximum
acceleration.
Now hear this. Maximum,
you're entitled to know,
means that we'll be
pushing our engines
well beyond safety limits.
Our hope is to surprise
whatever that is out there--
try and outrun it.
Our only other option
is to tuck tail
between our legs
and return to Earth
as they demand.
Engine Room ready, sir.
The board shows green,
Captain-- all go.
Stand by.
Engage.
Velocity warp 9.2.
Heading 3-5-1,
mark 11, sir.
Steady on that.
The hostile is now giving chase,
sir, accelerating fast.
We're now at warp 9.3, sir,
which takes us
past the red line.
PICARD:
Continue accelerating.
Counselor, at this point,
I'm open to guesses
about what we've just met.
It felt like
something beyond
what we'd consider
a life-form.
Beyond?
Very, very
advanced, sir,
or certainly very,
very... different.
WORF:
We're at 9.4, sir.
Hostile is now beginning
to overtake us, sir.
Are you sure?
Hostile's velocity
is already warp 9.6, sir.
Shall I put them
on the main viewer?
Reverse angle.
Magnifying
viewer image.
Hostile's velocity
is 9.7, sir.
PICARD:
Worf, inform the Engine Room
that we need more.
Engine Room attempting
to comply, sir,
but they caution us...
Go to yellow alert.
Arm aft photon torpedoes.
Place them on ready status.
Torpedoes to ready, sir.
Hostile now
at warp 9.8, sir.
Our velocity is only 9.5, sir.
DATA:
Projection, sir.
We may be able to
match hostile's 9.8, sir...
but at extreme risk.
Now reading the hostile
at warp 9.9, sir.
Now hear this.
Printout message, urgent,
all stations on all decks:
prepare for
emergency saucer-sep.
You will command
the saucer section, Lieutenant.
I am a Klingon, sir.
For me to seek escape when
my Captain goes into battle...
You are a Starfleet officer,
Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Make the mark, Data.
Note in ship's log
that at this startime,
I'm transferring command
to the Battle Bridge.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41153.7:
Preparing to detach
saucer section
so that families and the
majority of the ship's company
can seek relative safety
while the vessel's stardrive,
containing the Battle Bridge
and main armaments,
will turn back and confront
the mystery that
is threatening us.
Lieutenant, your
torpedoes must detonate
close enough
to the hostile
to blind it the
moment we separate.
Understood, sir.
All decks
acknowledging, sir.
Worf, this is the Captain.
At the moment of separation,
we will reverse power
just enough
to get your saucer section
out ahead and clear of us.
Understood, Captain.
Torpedoes away, sir.
Begin countdown.
Mark.
Starship separation...
six, five, four,
three, two, one.
Separation successful, sir.
Torpedoes have
detonated, sir.
Let's come to a stop.
Reverse power.
Decelerating.
Dead stop.
We'll hold this position
and wait for them.
That will bring them here
in just minutes, sir.
( sighs )
Will we make a fight of it,
Captain?
If we can at least damage
their ship, we have a chance --
Lieutenant, are you recommending
that we fight a life-form
that can do all those things?
I'd like to hear your advice.
I spoke before
I thought, sir.
We should look for some way
to distract them
from going after
the saucer.
O'BRIEN:
All forward
motion stopped, sir.
Thank you, Conn.
Commander,
signal the following
in all languages
and on all frequencies:
We surrender.
State that we are not asking
for any terms or conditions.
Aye, sir.
All language forms
and frequencies.
( laughter and jeering )
( laughing and talking )
( machine gun fire )
The prisoners will
all stand!
Historically intriguing,
Captain.
Very, very accurate.
Mid-21st century.
The post-atomic horror.
BAILIFF:
All present...
stand and make
respectful attention
to honored judge!
Careful, sir.
This is not an illusion
or a dream.
But these courts
belong in the past.
TROI:
I don't understand, either
but this is real.
Get to your
feet, criminals!
At least we're acquainted
with the judge, Captain.
Attention!
On your feet! Attention!
You are out of order!
The prisoners
will not be harmed...
...until they're found guilty.
Dispose of that.
Can we assume you mean
this will be a fair trial?
Yes, absolutely equitable.
BAILIFF:
Before this gracious court
now appear these prisoners
to answer for the multiple
and grievous savageries
of the species.
How plead you, criminal?
If I may, Captain...
Objection, Your Honor.
In the year 2036,
the new United Nations
declared that no Earth
citizen could be made
to answer for the crimes
of his race or forbears.
Objection denied.
This is a court
of the year 2079,
by which time
more rapid progress
had caused all "United Earth"
nonsense to be abolished.
Tasha, no!
I must, because
I grew up in a world
that allowed things
like this court,
and it was people like these
that saved me from it.
This so-called court
should get down on its knees
to what Starfleet is,
what it represents.
You barbarian!
This woman...
Criminals keep silence!
You've got a lot to
learn about humans
if you think you can torture us
or frighten us into silence.
Will she live?
Uncertain.
When he froze Lieutenant
Torres on the Bridge
we had our Sick Bay
to help thaw him out.
You will answer
the charges, criminal.
Or what? Or this?
Or death? Or worse?
You promised the prisoners
will not be harmed.
We plead nothing so long as
you break your own rules.
I suggest
you center your attention
on this trial, Captain.
It may be your only hope.
And I suggest you are now
having second thoughts about it.
You are considering that
if you conduct a fair trial,
which was your promise,
you may lose.
Lose?
Yes, even though
you're judge and prosecutor.
And jury.
Accepted...
so long as you keep
to your agreement,
and assaulting a prisoner
is hardly a fair trial!
This is a merciful court.
( bell tolling )
Silence!
Continuing
these proceedings,
I must caution you that legal
trickery is not permitted.
This is a
court of fact.
...court of fact!
We humans know our past
even when we're ashamed of it.
I recognize this court system
as the one that agreed
with that line from Shakespeare:
"Kill all the lawyers."
Which was done.
Leading to the rule
guilty until proven innocent.
Of course. Bringing the innocent
to trial would be unfair.
You will now answer
to the charge
of being a grievously
savage race.
Grievously savage
could mean anything.
I will answer
only specific charges.
Are you certain you want
a full disclosure
of human ugliness?
So be it, fool.
Present the charges!
Criminal, you will read
the charges to the court.
I see no charges
against us, Your Honor.
You are out of order.
Soldiers, you will
press those triggers
if this criminal answers
with any word other than guilty.
Criminal, how plead you?
Guilty...
...provisionally.
The court will hear
the provision.
We question
whether this court
is abiding by its own
trial instructions.
Have I your permission
to have Commander Data
repeat the record?
There will be no
legal trickery.
These will be
your own words, Your Honor.
What exactly followed
His Honor's statement
that the prisoners
will not be harmed?
Yes, sir.
The Captain had asked
the question
( in Picard's voice ):
"Can we assume you mean
this will be a fair trial?"
And in reply,
the judge stated,
( in Q's voice ):
"Yes, absolutely equitable."
Irrelevant testimony,
entirely irrelevant.
All right.
We agree there is evidence
to support
the court's contention
that humans have been savage.
Therefore, I say test us.
Test whether this is
presently true of humans.
I see, I see.
And so, you petition the court
to accept you and your comrades
as proof of what
humanity has become?
There must be many ways
we can be tested.
We have a long mission
ahead of us.
Another brilliant
suggestion, Captain,
but your test hardly
requires a long mission.
Your immediate destination
offers far more challenge
than you can
possibly imagine.
Yes,
this Farpoint Station
will be an excellent test.
All present,
respectfully stand.
This court is adjourned
to allow the criminals
to be tested.
This honorable court
is adjourned.
Stand respectfully.
Captain, you may find
that you are not
nearly clever enough to deal
with what lies ahead for you.
It may have been better
to accept sentence here.
What is present course, Conn?
It's what it's been
all along, sir--
direct heading
to Farpoint Station.
Confirmed.
We are on that heading, sir.
Do you know anything
about Farpoint Station, sir?
It sounds like
a fairly dull place.
We've heard that we may
find it rather interesting.
Personal Log,
Commander William Riker,
Stardate 41153.7:
The USS Hood has dropped me
off at Farpoint Station
where I await the arrival
of the new USS Enterprise
to which I have been assigned
as first officer.
Meanwhile,
I've been asked to visit
the Farpoint administrator's
office in the old city.
Ah, Commander Riker,
I thought you'd want to know
we've still no word
from your vessel.
I trust we've made your
waiting comfortable?
Luxurious is more like it.
Good.
Would I seem ungrateful
if I asked for some information?
Anything.
Fascinating
the advanced materials used
in constructing
this space station.
Your energy surplus must be
as abundant as I've heard.
Geothermal energy is one of the
great blessings of this planet.
I'll have all the details
of that sent to your quarters.
Thank you, but it still
seems incredible to me
that you could've constructed
this station so rapidly
and so...
and so perfectly suited
to our needs.
Would you care for
an Earth delicacy, Commander?
Well, if there's
an apple...
I'm sorry, Commander.
Oh, it doesn't matter.
What I was saying was...
I'll be damned.
Ah, yes.
There was another
selection here.
Groppler, I could have sworn
this wasn't here a minute ago.
And did your failure to notice
it make it unwelcome?
Not at all, Groppler.
I trust it will be the same with
Farpoint Station, Commander.
A few easily answered
questions about it
won't make Starfleet
appreciate it less.
And it's delicious.
Thank you.
Good morning,
Groppler Zorn.
Good morning.
You have been told
not to do that.
Why can't you understand?
It will arouse
their suspicion.
And if that happens,
we will have to punish you.
We will.
I promise you.
RIKER:
Dr. Crusher!
Mother.
It's Commander Riker.
Hello, Wes.
Enjoying Farpoint Station?
Yes, sir.
I saw you. I thought I might
join you for a stroll.
Actually, we were
about to do some shopping.
I've been meaning to
visit the mall myself.
Of course.
If you're wondering
about mom,
Commander Riker,
she's not unfriendly.
She's just shy around
men she doesn't know.
Wesley.
I believe that means
he would like us to be friends.
Oh, I'm willing,
Doctor.
Although we're
not officially part
of the Enterprise,
I thought there might be
something useful we could
do while we wait.
Useful? How, Commander?
Investigating some things
that I've noticed since
I've been here.
The last was...
Gold would be
lovely with this.
I had asked for an apple...
I am sure, Commander, there are
reasons for a first officer to
want to demonstrate his energy
and alertness to a new captain,
but since my duty
and interests
are outside
the command structure...
Remarkably happened to have
exactly what you asked for?
Thank you.
I'll take
the entire bolt.
Send it to our starship
when it arrives,
charge to Dr. Crusher.
Let's see,
where were we?
I was accusing you
of inventing work
in order to curry favor
with our new captain.
I apologize.
Mom, that gold pattern
wasn't there.
Maybe this
is something
Jean-Luc would
like looked into.
Jean-Luc Picard?
You know the Captain.
When I was little, he brought
my father's body home to us.
Yes, Wes--
long, long ago.
A pleasure to meet you,
Commander.
You will excuse us.
My pleasure, Doctor.
Wes.
Sir?
See you on board.
Yes, sir.
Sir, the Enterprise
is arriving, but...
Is this an official report,
Lieutenant?
Sorry, Commander.
Sir, Lieutenant La Forge
reporting the Enterprise
arriving,
but without
the saucer section, sir.
Stardrive section only?
What happened?
I don't know, sir.
Captain Picard has signaled
for you to beam up immediately.
Our new Captain
doesn't waste time.
It's a good idea.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Enterprise, this is Commander
Riker at Farpoint Station.
Standing by to beam up.
Lieutenant Yar
of Security, sir.
Captain Picard will see
you on the Battle Bridge.
With the saucer gone,
can I assume that
something interesting
happened on the way here?
Battle Bridge.
That's for the Captain
to explain, sir.
Do we have clearance?
Aye, sir, into
standard parking orbit.
Make it so.
Commander Riker, sir.
Riker, W.T.,
reporting as ordered, sir.
Is the viewer ready?
All set up, sir.
We'll first bring you up to date
on a little adventure
we had on our way here,
Commander.
Then we'll talk.
Welcome aboard.
This way, sir.
Thou art directed to return
to thine own
solar system immediately.
Go back, or thou shalt
most certainly die.
But you can't deny
that you're still
a dangerous,
savage child race.
Message from the
saucer module, sir.
It will arrive here
in 51 minutes.
Inform them we'll connect
as soon as they arrive.
And send the Commander to me
when he's finished.
YAR:
Yes, sir.
...and 400 years before that,
you were murdering each other
in quarrels
over tribal god images.
Since then,
there are no indications
that humans will ever change.
There are preparations to make,
but when we next meet, Captain,
we'll proceed
exactly as you suggest.
He calls that
a little adventure?
( door chime )
Come.
Not exactly a run-of-the-mill
happening, Captain.
It seems we're alive
only because we have been
placed on probation--
a very serious
kind of probation.
( beeping )
Go.
DATA:
The saucer module now
entering orbit with us, sir.
Acknowledged.
Commander Riker will conduct
a manual docking.
Picard out.
Sir?
You've reported in,
haven't you?
You are qualified?
Yes, sir.
Then I mean now, Commander.
You say you will be doing
this manually, sir?
No automation?
As ordered.
Velocity to one-half meter
per second.
Adjust pitch angle
negative three degrees.
Watch your roll angle, Conn.
All stations
prepare for reconnection.
Thrusters to station keeping.
All velocities zero.
Her inertia should
do the job now.
Lock up...
now.
A fairly routine maneuver,
but you handled it
quite well.
Thank you, sir.
I hope I show some promise.
I do have some questions
for you, however.
Yes, sir, I thought you might.
I see in your file
that Captain Desoto
thinks very highly of you.
One curious thing, however.
You refused to let him
beam down to Altair III.
In my opinion, sir,
Altair III was too dangerous
to risk exposing the Captain.
I see.
A Captain's rank
means nothing to you.
Rather the reverse, sir,
but a Captain's life means
a great deal more to me.
Isn't it just possible
that you don't get to be
a Starfleet Captain
without knowing whether
it's safe to beam down or not?
Isn't it a little presumptuous
of a first officer
to second-guess
his Captain's judgment?
Permission to speak
candidly, sir?
Always.
Having been
a first officer yourself,
you know that assuming
that responsibility
must, by definition, include
the safety of the Captain.
I have no problem with following
any rules you lay down--
short of compromising
your safety.
And you don't intend
to back off from that position?
No, sir.
One further thing.
A special favor.
Anything, sir.
Using the same strength
you showed with Captain Desoto,
I would appreciate it
if you could you keep me
from making an ass of
myself with children.
Sir?
I'm not a family man, Riker,
and yet Starfleet has given me
a ship with children aboard.
Yes, sir.
And I...
I don't feel comfortable
with children,
but since a Captain
needs an image of geniality,
you're to see
that's what I project.
Aye, sir.
Welcome to the Enterprise,
Commander Riker.
Naturally,
I've heard of your case.
The visor appliance
you wear is...
LA FORGE:
...is a remarkable piece
of bioelectronic engineering
by which I quote "see"
much of the EM spectrum,
ranging from simple heat
and infrared,
through radio waves,
et cetera, et cetera,
and forgive me if I've said
and listened to this
1,000 times before.
You've been blind
all your life?
Mm-hmm. I was born this way.
And you've felt pain all the
years that you've used this?
Hmm... They say it's because
I use my natural sensors
in different ways.
Well, I see two choices:
The first is
pain-killers.
Which would affect
how this works.
Mm-hmm.
No. And choice number two?
Exploratory surgery.
Desensitize the brain
areas troubling you.
Same difference.
No, thank you, Doctor.
I understand.
See you.
Yes, sir?
Where will I find
Commander Data?
Commander Data is
on special assignment, sir.
He's using our shuttlecraft
to transfer an admiral
over to the Hood.
An admiral?
He's been aboard all day, sir,
checking over medical layout.
Why a shuttlecraft?
Why wouldn't he just beam over?
I suppose he could, sir,
but the Admiral's a rather...
remarkable man.
Have you got some reason
you want my atoms
scattered all over space, boy?
No, sir.
But at your age, sir, I thought
you shouldn't have to put up
with the time and trouble
of a shuttlecraft.
Hold it right there, boy.
Sir?
What about my age?
Sorry, sir,
if that subject troubles you.
Troubles me?
What's so damned troublesome
about not having died?
How old do you think
I am, anyway?
137 years, Admiral,
according to Starfleet records.
Explain how you remember that
so exactly.
I remember every fact
I'm exposed to, sir.
I don't see no points
on your ears, boy,
but you sound like a Vulcan.
No, sir.
I am an android.
Hmm...
...almost as bad.
I thought it was
generally accepted, sir,
that Vulcans are an advanced
and most honorable race.
They are, they are.
And damn annoying at times.
Yes, sir.
Well, this is
a new ship,
but she's got
the right name.
Now you remember
that, you hear?
I will, sir.
You treat her like a lady
and she'll always
bring you home.
Did you signal the Hood,
Commander Riker?
Your exact message:
Bon voyage, mon ami.
Ah, what was the reply,
computer?
Q:
You're wasting time, Captain.
Or did you think I was gone?
Lieutenant!
Do you intend to
blast a hole in the viewer?
If the purpose of this
is to test humans,
Your Honor,
we must proceed
in our own way.
You are dilatory.
You have 24 hours.
Any further delay
and you risk summary judgment
against you, Captain.
Sorry, sir.
You reacted fast, Mr. Worf.
But futilely.
I will learn
to do better, sir.
Of course you will.
We've a long voyage
ahead of us.
What do we do now, Captain,
with them monitoring
our every move
and every word?
We do exactly what we'd do
if this Q never existed.
If we're going to be damned,
let's be damned
for what we really are.
PICARD:
Personal Log,
Stardate 41153.8:
Of the 24 hours Q allotted us
to prove ourselves,
11 have now passed
without incident.
And yet I cannot forget
Q's prediction
that we will face
some critical test.
This planet's interior heat
provides an abundance
of geothermal energy,
but it's about all
this world does offer.
And it's your belief that this
is what made it possible
for them to construct this
base to Starfleet standards?
Yes, sir.
We have to assume that
they've been trading
their surplus energy
for construction
materials used here.
According to our ship's scans,
many of the materials used
are not found on this world.
Perhaps it's like
those incidents
you describe in your report
as almost magical attempts
to please us.
Those events did happen, sir.
None of it suggests
anything threatening.
If only every life-form
had as much desire to please.
Ready to beam down?
I'm looking forward to meeting
this Groppler Zorn.
I've a feeling there's
more to it than just trying
to please us, sir.
As if it's something
Q is doing to trick us?
Over here.
I've asked the Counselor
to join us in this meeting.
May I introduce our
new first officer,
Commander William Riker.
Commander Riker, this is our
ship's counselor, Deanna Troi.
Do you remember
what I taught you, Imzadi?
Can you still
sense my thoughts?
A pleasure, Commander.
Likewise, Counselor.
Have the two
of you met before?
We have, sir.
Excellent.
I consider it important
for my key officers
to know each other's
abilities.
We do, sir.
We do.
I, too, could never
say good-bye, Imzadi.
My crew and I
need more information
before we can make our
recommendations to Starfleet.
No objections to that,
but I'm puzzled
over you bringing
a Betazoid to this meeting.
If her purpose, sir,
is to probe my thoughts...
I can sense only
strong emotions, Groppler.
I'm only half Betazoid.
My father was
a Starfleet officer.
I have nothing to hide,
of course.
Good, since we admire
what we've seen of
your construction techniques.
Starfleet may be interested
in your constructing
Starbases elsewhere, also.
We are not interested
in building other facilities.
If I may, Captain.
Then a trade, Groppler.
Some things that you need
in return for lending us
architects and engineers
who can demonstrate
your techniques.
Bandi do not enjoy leaving
their homeworld.
If Starfleet
cannot accept
that small weakness
then we will be forced,
unhappily,
to seek an alliance with someone
like the Ferengi...
( gasps softly )
Counselor,
what is it?
Do you want it
described here, sir?
Yes, no secrets here
if we're to be old friends,
agreed, Groppler?
But we ourselves have
nothing to hide, of course.
Pain.
Loneliness...
terrible loneliness.
Despair...
I'm not sensing Groppler, sir,
or any of his people,
but it's something
very close to us here.
PICARD:
The source of this, Groppler--
have you any idea?
No... no, absolutely not.
And I find nothing helpful
or productive in any of this.
And that's it?
No other comment?
Well, what do you expect of us?
We offer you a base
designed to your needs,
luxurious by even
human standards...
While evading even our
simplest questions about it.
We'll adjourn for now.
While we all reconsider
our positions.
Captain!
The Ferengi would be very
interested in a base like this!
Fine. Let's hope
they find you
as tasty as they did
their past associates.
Ensign, could you help me
find Commander Data?
I understand
he's somewhere on this deck.
This way, sir.
You must be new to these
Galaxy-class starships, sir.
Tell me the location
of Commander Data.
Lieutenant Commander Data
now located
in Holodeck area 4-J.
And as you can see, sir,
it's pointing you that way.
Thank you.
You're welcome, sir.
The next hatchway on your right.
Thank you.
You're welcome,
Commander Riker.
And if you care to enter,
Commander...
I do.
Hello!
(whistling
"Pop Goes the Weasel")
Marvelous how easily
humans do that.
I still need much practice.
There's some
puzzles down on...
...down on the planet
that the Captain wants answered.
He suggested I take you
with me on the away team
that I'll be leading.
I shall endeavor
to function adequately, sir.
Yes.
When the Captain suggested you,
I looked up your record.
Yes, sir. A wise
procedure, sir, always.
Then your rank of Lieutenant
Commander is honorary?
No, sir.
Starfleet class of '78.
Honors in probability
mechanics and exobiology.
But your file says
that you're a...
A machine. Correct, sir.
Does that trouble you?
To be honest,
yes, a little.
Understood, sir.
Prejudice is very human.
Now that does trouble me.
Do you consider yourself
superior to us?
I am superior, sir,
in many ways.
But I would gladly
give it up to be human.
Nice to meet you...
Pinocchio.
A joke.
Ah! Intriguing.
You're going to be an
interesting companion, Mr. Data.
This woodland pattern
is quite popular, sir,
perhaps because it
duplicates Earth so well.
Coming here almost makes
me feel human myself.
I didn't believe these
simulations could be this real.
Much of it is real, sir.
If the transporters
can convert our bodies
into an energy beam
then back to
the original pattern...
Yes, of course, and these
rocks and vegetation
have much simpler
patterns.
Correct, sir.
The rear wall.
I can't see it.
We're right next to it.
Incredible.
WESLEY:
Commander Riker!
Commander Riker,
isn't this great?
This is one
of the simple patterns.
They've got thousands more.
Some you just can't believe.
Careful, the next rock
is loose!
Wesley!
Wow!
( holodeck door opens )
Mr. Data has agreed to join me
on the away team, Captain.
Very good, Commander.
Sir, maybe I should get
something to wipe this water up?
Good idea.
There's a low-gravity
gymnasium, too.
It would be hard
to get bored on this ship.
Good.
Mom, could you get me
a look at the Bridge?
That's against
the Captain's standing orders.
Are you afraid
of the Captain, too?
I certainly am not.
But Captain Picard
is a pain, isn't he?
Your father
liked him very much.
Great explorers
are often lonely--
no chance to have a family.
Just a look
at the Bridge.
I'll stay in the turbolift
when the doors open.
I won't get off.
You are asking
for trouble, Wes.
We'll see what we can do.
YAR:
Recommend that
someone could begin
by examining the underside
of the station, sir.
Our sensors do show
some passages, sir.
Perhaps you and I.
Tasha, you and the Counselor.
And, Geordi, I want
your eyes down there.
You and I will start topside.
Have you noticed
anything unusual?
I can't see as well
as Geordi, sir,
but so far, the material
seems rather ordinary.
Construction records?
Construction records
shows this to be
almost identical to that
which Starfleet uses.
YAR:
Team leader.
We found something interesting.
We're in a passageway directly
under the station, sir.
But these tunnel walls
are something
I've never seen before, sir.
How are you
examining them, Geordi?
In every way: microscopically,
thermally, electromagnetically.
None of it
is familiar.
RIKER:
And what about you, Troi?
Sir, I've avoided
opening my mind.
Whatever I felt
in the Groppler's office
became very uncomfortable.
I'm sorry, Counselor, but you
must, we need more information.
Pain.
Such pain.
Hang on. I'm coming.
Enterprise, lock us on
to her signal.
I'm sorry.
Close your mind
to the pain.
Unhappiness.
Terrible despair.
Who?
I don't know.
No life-form
anything like us.
What in the hell kind
of place is this?
Geordi, what do you see?
Well, it's of...
it's of no material
I recognize, sir,
or have even heard of.
What the hell...
Children are not allowed
on the Bridge.
Permission to report
to the Captain.
Dr. Crusher.
Captain.
Sir, my son is not
on the Bridge.
He merely accompanied me
on the turbolift.
Your son?
His name's Wesley.
You last saw him
years ago when...
Well...
...as long as he's here.
I, uh...
I knew...
I knew your father, Wesley.
Want to look around?
But don't touch anything.
Try it out.
The panel on your right
is for log entries,
library-computer access
and retrieval,
view screen control
and intercoms and so on.
Here we have...
On here, the backup
conn and ops panels
plus shield
and armament controls.
The forward view screen
is controlled from
the ops position...
...which uses high-resolution,
multispectral imaging sensors.
How the hell do you
know that, boy?
( alarm blaring )
Perimeter alert, Captain!
Wesley!
I'm sorry, I didn't...
Wes, you shouldn't have
touched anything.
Get off the Bridge,
both of you.
We have a perimeter
alert, sir.
As my son tried to tell you.
Picard. Go ahead.
SECURITY:
Ship's sensors have
detected the presence
of a vessel
approaching this planet.
No ship is scheduled
to arrive at this time, sir.
Have Commander Riker
and his team beam back up.
Security, could that be
the Hood returning here?
The vessel does not match
the Hood's configuration
or ID signal.
Put it on main viewer.
Identification?
Vessel unknown,
configuration unknown, sir.
Hail it.
We've been trying, sir--
no response.
Raise all shields.
Phasers at ready.
Shields up, sir,
phasers ready.
PICARD:
Get me Groppler Zorn
and continue universal
greetings on all frequencies.
This is Zorn, Captain.
Zorn, an unidentified vessel
has entered into orbit with us.
Do you know who it is?
There are no ships scheduled
to arrive until...
I asked you
if you knew who it is.
You mentioned the
Ferengi alliance to me.
But we've had
no dealings with them.
It was only a... a thought.
Are you certain?
I promise you, Captain.
We were making an empty threat.
I wanted your cooperation.
Forgive me.
Definitely entering
orbital trajectory, sir.
It measures 12 times
our volume, Captain.
The sensors say we were
just scanned, sir.
Pain again?
Troi, you've been
at it enough.
No.
I feel close to
an answer of some kind.
Commander, something down here
is shielding our communicators.
Yes.
That's exactly the feeling
I've been reading--
as if someone doesn't want us
to be in touch with our ship.
Come on.
Let's get to the surface.
There is no computer record
of any such vessel, sir.
Nothing even close.
Still no response, sir.
We've done everything
but threaten them.
Sensor scans,
Mr. Worf.
Our sensor signals
just seem to bounce off.
Something's happening, sir.
They're firing
on Farpoint, sir.
Bring photon torpedoes
to ready.
Wait, sir.
They're hitting the old Bandi
city, not Farpoint Station.
Those stairs are where
we entered down here, sir.
At this point it becomes
ordinary stone, sir,
matching what's above.
My God, was that
a phaser blast?
DATA:
Negative, but something similar.
You, Tasha, and Geordi
will beam up to the ship now.
Come on. I want to see
exactly what's happening.
Don't! If you should be hurt...
You have your
orders, Lieutenant.
Carry them out.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Enterprise,
three to beam up.
Enterprise, Enterprise,
come in.
Help us, please.
What shall we do?
Enterprise, help us, please!
Tune that down.
Commander Riker, come in.
Can you hear me?
Riker to Enterprise,
come in.
PICARD:
Commander Riker, come in.
Where are you?
With Data, on the edge
of the old city, sir.
It's being hit
hard, sir.
And Farpoint Station?
Any damage there?
Negative on damage
to Farpoint, sir.
Whoever they are,
they're carefully avoiding
hitting the Station.
It's from
an unidentified vessel
that's entered
into orbit with us here.
No ID, no answer
to our signals.
The old Bandi city's
being hit hard, sir.
Many casualties
very probable.
Understand, Commander.
Would you object to
your Captain ordering
a clearly illegal kidnapping?
No objection, sir.
Groppler Zorn may have
the answers we need.
Get him-- bring him here.
Aye, sir.
They're forcing a very difficult
decision on me, Counselor.
But I doubt protecting
the Bandi would violate
the Prime Directive.
True, they are not
actual allies, but...
We are in the midst of
diplomatic discussions
with them.
Lieutenant, lock
phasers on that vessel.
Phasers locked on,
Captain.
Typical, so typical.
Savage life-forms never follow
even their own rules.
Get off my Bridge!
Interesting, that
order about phasers.
Standing by
on phasers, Captain.
Please, don't let me interfere.
Use your weapons.
With no idea of who
is on that vessel,
my order was a routine
safety precaution.
Really? No idea of
what it represents?
The meaning of that
vessel is as plain...
as plain as the noses
on your ugly little
primate faces.
And if you were truly
civilized, Captain,
wouldn't you be doing something
about the casualties
happening down there?
Captain to CMO.
Are you reading any of this?
Medical teams already preparing
to beam down, Captain.
Compliments
on that, Doctor.
Any questions?
Starfleet people are trained
to render aid and assistance
whenever...
But not trained
in clear thinking.
Let's consider
your thoughts.
You call us savages
and yet you knew
those people down there
were going to be killed.
It is your conduct
that is uncivilized.
Sir, they're firing
on the planet again.
Go to maneuvering jets.
Position us between
that vessel and the planet.
Force fields full on.
Aye, sir.
Impulse power to...
We have no ship control, sir.
It's gone.
Are you undamaged?
Yes. You?
All systems operating.
( sobbing )
Please. Make it stop!
You can drive it away.
Drive who away,
Groppler?
I don't know.
DATA:
Unlikely, sir.
Our records show
you supervised
all Bandi contact
with other worlds.
We've done nothing wrong.
Then if we can learn
nothing from you...
we'll leave.
No! Oh, no, please,
don't leave.
I'll... try to explain.
( screaming )
First Officer
to Enterprise.
We've lost Zorn.
Something like
a transporter beam
seems to have
snatched him away.
Question, sir.
Could it be this Q?
None of you knows
who transported him.
You're running out
of time, Captain.
Captain, suddenly
I'm sensing something else.
Satisfaction.
Enormous satisfaction.
PICARD:
From the same source
as before?
No, that was on the planet.
This is much closer.
Excellent, Counselor.
He's such a dullard,
isn't he?
Captain,
from Transporter Room:
First Officer and Mr. Data
have beamed aboard.
Excellent, also.
Perhaps with more of
these little minds helping...
That is enough, damn it!
Have you forgotten that
we have an agreement?
An agreement which
you are, at this moment,
breaking by taking
over our vessel
interfering with my decisions.
Either leave or finish us!
Temper, temper,
mon capitaine.
I'm merely trying to
assist a pitiful species,
but perhaps I will leave...
if Commander Riker provides me
with some amusement.
Do nothing that he asks.
But I ask so little,
and it's so necessary
if you're to
solve all this.
Beam over there with
your what do you call it?
Your "away team"?
I'll risk none of my crew
on that unknown.
You should already know
what you'll find there,
but perhaps it's too adult
a puzzle for you.
With all respect, Captain,
I want to beam over there.
You show promise,
my good fellow.
Have you understood any part
of what he's tried to tell you?
Humanity is no longer
a savage race.
But you must still
prove that.
At least you impressed him,
Number One.
That's hopeful.
Thank you, Captain.
Captain, if he's not open
to evidence in our favor,
where will you go
from there?
I'll attend to my duty.
To the bitter end?
I see nothing
so bitter about that.
Can I help you, Captain?
I, uh...
I didn't want you thinking me
harsh, cold-blooded.
Why, oh, why
would I ever think that?
I didn't welcome you aboard
personally, professionally.
I made you come to me
on the Bridge.
I yelled at your son,
who, as you pointed out,
was quite correct.
He does seem to have
a very good grasp of
starship operations.
You've just won
this mother's heart, Captain.
Ah.
But, now,
your assignment here...
I would...
consider and approve
a transfer for you.
Oh.
Do you consider me
unqualified?
Hardly.
Your service record shows
you're just the chief
medical officer I want.
Then you must object to me
personally.
I'm trying to be considerate
of your feelings, Doctor.
For you to work
with a commanding officer
who would
continually remind you
of a terrible,
personal tragedy...
If I had had any objections
to serving with you,
I wouldn't have requested
this assignment, Captain.
You requested this posting?
My feelings about my husband's
death will have no effect
on the way I serve you,
this vessel, or this mission.
Ah.
Then welcome aboard,
Doctor.
Riker to Picard.
We're ready to beam over, sir.
I, uh...I hope
we can be friends.
Thank you.
Phasers on stun.
Energize.
Most interesting, sir.
Much the same
construction we saw
in the underground tunnel.
But no sound of power.
No equipment.
How does this ship run?
( gasp of pain )
What is it, Troi?
Is it the same
as you felt down there?
No.
This is much
more powerful.
Full of anger.
Hate.
Toward us?
No.
It's directed down
toward the old Bandi city.
Most intriguing
again, sir.
The place that
this vessel was
firing upon
was not the
Farpoint Starbase
but the home of those
who constructed...
Sorry, sir.
I seem to be
commenting on everything.
Good.
Don't stop, my friend.
Enterprise, Riker.
This is turning out to be a very
long tunnel or corridor, sir.
No ship's crew in sight.
No sign of mechanism
or circuitry.
No controls or readouts.
This is nothing like
any vessel I've seen before.
Groppler Zorn, sir...
in great fear, just ahead.
There is a different feeling
here than in the tunnel.
Very different.
ZORN ( in distance ):
No, please! No more, please!
No more!
Please, make it stop the pain!
Please...
make it stop the pain!
No, please! No more!
Please! No more!
Please!
Zorn, can you hear me?
Make it stop the pain!
( screaming )
Has the alien communicated?
Please!
That's it, sir.
It's just one alien
I'm sensing here.
Please, I don't understand
what you want!
Not true.
He does know.
ZORN:
No, please! No more!
Please! No more!
( crying )
No! Don't! Don't!
Captain!
PICARD:
Transporter Chief,
yank them back-- now!
Riker, acknowledge.
Your time is up, Captain.
Transporter Chief,
do you have their coordinates?
Transporter Chief!
He can't hear you, Captain.
Transporter Chief, come in!
I've people in trouble
over there, Q.
Everyone at ease.
That's an order.
Q, my people are in trouble.
Let me help them, please.
I'll do whatever you say.
You'll do whatever I say?
Seems I did make
that bargain.
The agreement
isn't valid, sir.
It wasn't Q that saved us.
Save yourself.
It may attack you now.
It was that which
sent us back, Captain.
Yes, sir. It is not merely
a vessel-- somehow it is alive.
She lies! Destroy it
while you have a chance.
Make phasers and
photon torpedoes ready.
No, do nothing
he demands.
Captain, that thing
was killing my people.
Was there a reason?
It is an unknown, Captain.
Isn't that enough?
If you'd earned that
uniform you're wearing,
you'd know that the unknown
is what brings us out here.
Wasted effort,
considering human intelligence.
Let's test that!
Beginning with the tunnels you
have under Farpoint, Groppler.
Identical to those on the space
vessel life-form over there.
Why was it punishing you,
Groppler?
In return for some pain
you've given another creature?
We've done nothing wrong!
It was injured.
We helped it.
Thank you.
That was the
missing element.
Lieutenant Yar, rig main phaser
banks to deliver an energy beam.
Aye, sir.
You're right, Captain.
It has to be conceivable
that somewhere in this galaxy
there could exist creatures able
to convert energy into matter.
And into specific
patterns of matter
just as our transporters do.
On the viewer, Captain.
Groppler...
you captured something
like that, didn't you?
Warn my people, please, to leave
Farpoint Station immediately!
He lies, Captain.
Shouldn't you let
his people die?
Transmit the message:
"Leave Farpoint Space
Station immediately."
TROI:
Then it was a pair
of creatures I was sensing--
one down there
in grief and pain,
the other up here,
filled with anger.
DATA:
And firing not on
the new space station,
but on the Bandi
and their city.
Attacking those
who had captured...
captured its mate.
Energy beam ready, sir.
Lock it in on
Farpoint Station.
I see now it was
too simple a puzzle.
Generosity has always
been my... weakness.
Let it have whatever
it can absorb.
Energize.
Now getting feedback
on the beam, sir.
Discontinue it.
Groppler Zorn...
there will soon be
no Farpoint Station
if I'm right about this.
Lucky guess!
Please believe me,
we meant no harm
to the creature.
It was starving for energy.
Which your world furnishes
you in plenty.
And we did feed it.
But only enough
to keep it alive
so that you could force
it to shape itself
into whatever
form you needed.
Sir...
it's wonderful!
A feeling of great joy...
and gratitude.
Great joy...
and gratitude...
from both of them.
Why...
do you use other life-forms
for your recreation?
If so, you've not
provided the best...
Leave us! We've passed
your little test.
Temper, temper,
mon capitaine.
Get off my ship.
I do so only because
it suits me to leave.
But I will not promise
never to appear again.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41174.2:
The agreement
for the rebuilding
of Farpoint Station
has been completed
per my instructions.
All stations?
Ready for departure, sir.
Some problem, Riker?
Just hoping this isn't
the usual way
our missions
will go, sir.
Oh, no, Number One.
I'm sure most will be
much more interesting.
Let's see what's out there.
Engage.