Captain's Log,
Stardate 41209.2:
We are running at warp 7
to rendezvous
with the science vessel
S.S. Tsiolkovsky--
which has been routinely
monitoring the collapse
of a red supergiant star
into a white dwarf.
What has brought us here
is a series of strange messages
indicating something
has gone wrong
aboard the research vessel.
( party noises )
S.S. Tsiolkovsky,
repeat your message.
FEMALE:
Well, hello, Enterprise.
Welcome.
I hope you have a lot
of pretty boys onboard
because I'm willing
and waiting
if in fact, we're going to have
a real blowout here.
( wild party sounds )
MALE:
Do it! Yeah, go ahead.
( laughing ):
Do it!
( explosion )
Captain, what we've just
heard is... impossible.
Report.
I believe
that last sound
was an emergency
hatch being blown.
Are you certain?
Yes, of course you are.
Data, Geordi, Tasha.
Sensor scans now reveal
no life signs
aboard, Captain.
( alarm blaring )
Cover the ship
as planned.
Move out.
Indications of what humans
would call... a wild party.
Yeah.
( electrical fritzing )
Their Bridge.
If this thing works,
be sure to record everything.
You were right.
Somebody blew out the hatch.
They were all sucked out
into space.
Correction, sir--
that's blown out.
Thank you, Data.
A common mistake, sir.
Commander Riker, Lieutenant Yar,
location engineering.
Ten people here, sir,
all frozen.
No vital signs.
Frozen? How?
Looks like someone
has been playing
with the environmental
controls, sir.
Just let all the heat
bleed away into space.
( shivers )
Sir, Lieutenant La Forge
in the crew quarters.
There's something in here.
( rhythmic banging )
( high-pitched whooshing )
Riker to Captain,
I have a report for you, sir.
Picard here.
They're all dead.
Apparently some of them were
blown out the emergency hatches.
But there were 80 people
on that ship, Number One.
Yes, sir.
As I said...
all dead.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
We are downloading
the research information
gathered on
the collapsing star nearby.
I am concerned at being
in such close orbit
but the Tsiolkovsky's
research records
will no doubt predict the time
of the star's final collapse.
I can't find
anything unusual
in any of the tricorder readings
they sent over, Captain.
Give me a theory, Doctor.
Anything.
Madness?
Mass hysteria?
Delusion?
Any, or all, Captain.
All right, let's bring
the away team back.
Set the transporter
to maximum
decontamination
and then full
examination
and observation
when they're here.
If you were
any more perfect, Data
I'd have to write you up
in a Starfleet Medical
textbook.
I'm already listed in several
biomechanical texts, Doctor.
Yes, of course.
You're next, Lieutenant.
( beeping )
Normal all across.
Except... why are you
perspiring, Lieutenant?
I suppose because you
have it too hot in here.
What else
would it be?
That doesn't sound
like you, Geordi.
Well, maybe it's not.
Maybe she threw her voice.
Hey, it was a joke.
Of course, but I
would like to run
one or two more tests
on you, Lieutenant.
( sighing )
Sick Bay to Bridge.
Picard here.
Go ahead, Doctor.
I'm confining
Lieutenant La Forge to Sick Bay
until further notice.
Do we have a problem, Doctor?
I don't know yet.
Data, I need help
in locating some library
computer information.
Specifics, sir?
All I have is a vague memory
of reading somewhere
about someone taking a shower
in his or her clothing.
Ah, the body Geordi discovered.
Well, I believe
it may have happened before.
To someone, somewhere.
This ought to be easy
for someone written up
in biomechanical texts.
About that, sir.
Did the Doctor
believe I was boasting?
Probably.
This may take some time?
At least several hours.
But what I said was
a statement of fact.
Perhaps she will look it up.
You can depend on it.
Geordi!
Security, Lieutenant La Forge
just left Sick Bay
while I was in my office.
He doesn't have
his communicator.
It is very important
that we find him.
Security team alert.
Pick up Lieutenant
La Forge.
He just left Sick
Bay moments ago.
Captain,
anything further?
Affirmative.
Make it a shipwide
search, Lieutenant.
It's a model of the same kind
of tractor beam our ship uses--
with a few ideas
of my own added.
So that's your
science project, huh?
Wes, you're
really something.
And since the Captain
won't let me on the Bridge,
I use this to imagine
I'm there.
PICARD:
Take the helm, Mr. Crusher.
Set a course for 37 mark 180,
warp 6.
That's the Captain's voice.
It's pieced together from words
he's used on the intercom.
With this,
I can pretend
he's ordering me to take
the Enterprise anywhere
and listen to this.
Chief Engineer,
report to the Bridge.
Commander Riker, report to the
Bridge.
Dr. Crusher,
report to the Bridge.
What do you think?
I think the Captain's
lucky you're on his side.
But he still won't let me
on the Bridge
and there's nothing there
I don't understand.
I wish I understood
myself that well.
Are you okay?
No, suddenly I seem to
be burning up inside.
( sighing )
It's so hot in here!
Geordi.
Geordi!
Lieutenant Yar in
the observation lounge.
Send a team here now.
Medical's been
worried about you.
Help me.
Help me to
not give in
to the wild things
coming into my mind.
Geordi, my job is security.
Tasha, please.
All right.
Helping is more important.
Geordi, how can I help you?
Help me to see
like you do.
But you already see
better than I can.
I see more.
But more isn't better.
Geordi, please
put these back...
I want to see
in shallow, dim,
beautiful, human ways.
We'll talk about it, Geordi.
Right now I'm going
to take you to Sick Bay.
All right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Good.
And then we got him down
to Sick Bay
so Dr. Crusher
could examine him.
He wasn't violent?
No, sir.
He was very upset.
He kept talking about
wanting normal vision.
Hmm.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
( sighing )
According to our
medical readouts
there's still nothing wrong
with him.
He looks like he's
running a temperature
but every instrument we have
says he's not.
Doctor, every person
on that ship over there died.
Is there any chance
that whatever did it
is loose on my ship?
If you mean a disease, sir,
I'd say there's no chance of it.
We used full
decontamination.
We examined every team member
very carefully.
The entire crew somehow managed
to kill themselves, Doctor.
If it's not a disease,
what else made them do it?
The obvious alternatives
are in the areas of insanity
and severe emotional upset.
Troi, do you feel anything
unusual in
the Lieutenant?
Security just told me
that he was longing
for normal sight.
That's a sudden
yearning for that.
Since his records show
no previous mention of that,
the fact that it happened
now could be important.
But all I sense from him
is confusion.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say he was intoxicated.
Our tests would have
shown that--
also any other signs of drugs,
hallucinogens,
or any other contaminants.
( sighing )
Can you provide
more information, sir?
Seeking an instance
of someone showering
in his or her clothing is...
I know. It's like looking
for a needle in a haystack.
Why should anyone
wish to expend his
time in such a search?
Correction, Data.
I should have said
proverbial needle
in a haystack.
A human proverb--
as in folklore
or an historical allusion
or tribal memories.
Historical. That's it.
I remember I was reading
a history
of all the past starships
named Enterprise.
Enterprise history.
Aberrant behavior.
Medical cross-reference.
Captain, I believe
we have the answer
to what happened
over there.
The Constitution-class
Starship Enterprise
Captain James T. Kirk,
commanding.
Similar conditions.
They were monitoring
a planet that was breaking up
and not a collapsing star,
as in this case.
But there were the same
huge shifts in gravity.
Which somehow resulted
in complex strings
of water molecules
which acquired carbon
from the body
and acted...
acted on the brain like alcohol.
Data, download
this information to
Medical immediately.
Aye, sir.
Downloading.
Fascinating.
The entire crew
going out of control.
Like intoxication,
but worse.
Judgment almost
completely impaired.
Until they found this formula,
barely in time.
Picard to Dr. Crusher.
Come in.
This is Crusher.
Go ahead, Captain.
You can relax, Doctor.
The answer to all of this
is feeding into
your medical banks right now--
including a cure.
Are you certain, Captain?
Absolutely.
( laughter )
Tasha?
What are
you doing?
I need your advice.
That's why I came
to your quarters.
Of course. Anything...
On clothes.
You always wear
such beautiful clothes off duty.
And your hair always
looks so nice.
I want to change my image.
What do you think
about this?
Or this one?
It's not for you.
Tasha...
I feel you're very uncertain.
That you're fighting something.
( high-pitched whooshing )
What is it?
Never mind.
I'll find what
I need myself.
Ship's stores
will have it.
Tasha.
Tasha, wait!
Troi to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
Sir, I think
Tasha's been infected, too.
She just left my quarters.
Counselor, it's not
actually an infection.
Yes, sir, it's more
like an intoxication
but whatever it is,
she's got it.
Thank you, Counselor.
Number One
it seems our
security chief
has the equivalent
of a snootful.
Inquiry, sir.
Snootful?
Forget it.
Hey, Mom, look
what I can do.
I've been able to widen
and strengthen the beam--
just like I told
you last night.
Do me a favor, Wes.
There's something
happening on this ship.
Just to be safe,
I'd like you to stay
in our quarters
until it's solved.
Sure, Mom, sure.
Your wish is my command.
Now, Wes.
Okay, but you could be
stunting my emotional growth.
You realize that?
Why's it so hot in here,
anyway?
Picard to Crusher.
Crusher here.
Have you made
a test injection yet?
We're getting indications that
this condition is spreading.
No test yet, Captain,
but very soon.
( high-pitched whooshing )
Captain, another 41 minutes
will see the information
from the Tsiolkovsky
downloaded to us.
Why so slow?
Slow, sir?
The Tsiolkovsky has been
eight months in accumulating it.
How much danger from that star--
worst case?
Like a full collapse, sir?
Any stellar material
it threw this way
we could still outrun
on half impulse power.
Picard to Engineering.
Chief Engineer,
report to the Bridge.
Assistant Chief Engineer
Shimoda, report to Medical.
Hi, Jim.
Was that the Captain
ordering you to Medical?
Which would leave
no one here on duty.
The Chief was just
summoned to the Bridge.
What about me?
I could call the
Chief on the Bridge
if anything happened.
Reporting as ordered, sir.
What?
You ordered me to report
to the Bridge, sir.
I did no such thing.
I want you down
in the engine room
just in case we need
to move out of here.
PICARD:
Attention, all decks
all divisions.
Effective immediately
I have handed over
control of this vessel
to acting Captain
Wesley Crusher.
Acting Captain?!
WESLEY:
Thank you, Captain Picard,
thank you.
And with that order
dawns a brave new day
for the Enterprise.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41209.3:
The strange contaminant
that led to the deaths
of the Tsiolkovsky crew is now
aboard the Enterprise
and our engineering section
has been commandeered
by young Wesley Crusher.
And henceforth
a dessert course shall
precede and follow every meal
including breakfast.
Hooray for the
acting captain!
Never got as far
as Sick Bay, Wes.
I feel too good for that.
( laughter )
Incredible!
How did you do that?
Hooked my model tractor beam
into ship's power.
Now it's a repulser beam, too.
Want in?
Swear to be faithful to you,
Captain.
Number One, MacDougal, get
that boy out of Engineering.
Sir.
I'm getting very strange
reports from all decks.
Such as?
Such as the ship's training
division ordering all officers
to attend a lecture
on metaphysics.
Metaphysics?
Confirmed, sir.
And there was
a rather peculiar limerick
being delivered by someone
in the shuttlecraft bay.
I am not sure
I understand it.
"There was a young lady
from Venus
whose body was
shaped like a..."
Captain to Security, come in!
Did I say something wrong?
I don't understand
their humor either.
Yeah, Captain.
Where is my security chief?!
Get me Lieutenant Yar!
Keep your britches on.
YAR:
Captain Picard.
Lieutenant, where are you?
I'm in my quarters
and, um... I'm pretty busy
right at the moment,
Jean-Luc.
All right, Lieutenant,
you just stay right there.
Data.
Go to
Lieutenant Yar.
Take her down to Sick Bay.
Aye, sir.
Captain to Security, I want
all your senior supervisors
to report to
the Bridge immediately.
( giggling )
Lieutenant Yar?
Here, Data.
You wanted me?
Captain Picard ordered me
to escort you to Sick Bay,
Lieutenant.
Did he say when?
I'm sure he meant now.
So you should get
into uniform.
But I got out of my uniform
for you, Data.
Do you know how old I was
when I was abandoned?
Chronological age?
No, I'm afraid
I am not familiar with...
Five. Five years old.
But I survived.
I learned how to stay alive,
how to avoid the rape gangs.
I was 15 before I escaped.
I am sorry.
I did not know.
And what I want now
is gentleness
and joy
and love...
from you, Data.
You are fully functional,
aren't you?
Of course, but...
How fully?
In every way, of course.
I am programmed in
multiple techniques--
a broad variety
of pleasuring...
Oh! You jewel!
That's exactly what I hoped.
What have you learned,
Number One?
Captain, the ship's engines are
cut off from the Bridge.
The Assistant Chief Engineer
has pulled out the isolinear
optical chips from command.
All the engines are off-line.
Wesley has hooked up
some kind of tractor beam
to the ship's power.
He has it aimed at the door.
And we can't get past
to get to the computer.
Can you short out the power?
Yes, I can, but it's
going to take some time.
Do it!
Bill.
Deanna, what?
So many minds on this ship...
all free...
released.
Deanna.
I can feel them all...
what they want...
what they feel.
It's a side of humans
I never felt before.
( high-pitched whooshing )
Come on.
I'm getting you
to Sick Bay.
Wouldn't you rather
be alone with me?
With me in your mind?
The medical records we found
say this works almost instantly.
It's not fair, Doc.
I've never seen
a rainbow...
a sunset...
sunrise.
This is going
to help me?
Help me see
like you?
Dr. Crusher.
( high-pitched whooshing )
Deanna needs your help.
The formula
from the old Enterprise
didn't work.
What?
This water-carbon
complex may induce
the same symptoms but
somehow it's different.
Maybe it's mutated.
But I've got to isolate it
in order to analyze it.
We don't have
that kind of time.
You brought Deanna in.
Yes, she's infected.
Then you touched her.
Oh, God, and you touched me.
Wait, I've got
to quarantine you.
If I don't get the command
computer back on-line soon
none of this-- whatever
this is-- will matter.
We'll all be dead.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
It is no longer an inconvenient
childish prank.
Young Wesley Crusher--
admittedly a victim of
the Tsiolkovsky infection
is now in control
of my starship.
Wesley, this is Captain Picard.
Do you see me?
Yes, sir.
You will now
return control
of this vessel
to the Bridge where
it belongs, at once.
I'm sorry, sir.
Why don't you just tell me
what you want done
and I'll do it.
Because ship captains control
their own vessels, young man!
But, sir, you don't
do it yourself.
You give the orders,
but somebody else does it.
What's wrong with
giving me the orders to do it?
Captain, getting
unusual readings now
from the
dwarf star.
Stand by on that for a moment.
Wesley!
Wes, are you aware
that you are behaving strangely?
That a kind of infection
was brought over
from the Tsiolkovsky
which acts
like intoxication?
Are you saying
that's why I feel so hot
and so strange?
That's... that's a very adult
bit of reasoning, Wesley.
So, you mean I'm drunk!
I feel strange but also good.
Because...
because you have lost
the capacity for self-judgment.
Now, alcohol does this, Wesley
but the contaminant we brought
back from the Tsiolkovsky
does it even more so.
What would you do
if you got your ship back?
Oh... it's very important
I do, Wesley
because I must immediately lock
a tractor beam
onto the Tsiolkovsky--
and tow it out of...
Tractor beams
are my specialty, skipper!
I'll contact you
when that's done.
Wesley out!
Wesley! Wesley!
Conn?
Where are you headed?
Sir! The star.
It's beginning to collapse.
What the hell is happening
in Engineering?
Lock on.
Lock on, Tsiolkovsky.
Come on, now.
Where's that
sonic driver?
It's over there.
Okay. Let's see if this
cuts out his tractor beam power.
Come on.
No, no.
I must find the answer.
I've got to find the answer.
Captain, tractor beam.
We just locked on
to the Tsiolkovsky.
Captain to...
Wesley!
Wesley Crusher, come in.
Ah, good. Data.
At least you're functioning.
Fully, Captain.
Data, intoxication is
a human condition.
Your brain is different.
It's not the same as...
We are more alike than
unlike, my dear Captain.
I have pores.
Humans have pores.
I have...
fingerprints.
Humans have fingerprints.
My chemical nutrients
are like your blood.
If you prick me...
do I not... leak?
Doctor...
Captain, can I see you
in your ready room?
It's a private matter.
No, actually,
it's an urgent one.
But...
Damn it.
Now, Doctor.
I believe I've become infected
myself, Captain.
Do you know what
the infection is?
( giggles )
Come on. Quickly!
Sorry.
It is definitely like
alcohol intoxication--
the same lack of good judgment.
For example, right now,
I find you extremely...
extremely...
Of course, we haven't time
for that sort of thing.
What sort of thing?
Oh, God, would I love
to show you.
Doctor, there
must be a cure.
Some formula...
( clears throat )
...similar to
the old one.
Damn it, damn it,
Captain.
My dear Captain.
You owe me something.
You do realize
that, don't you?
I'm a woman.
I haven't had the comfort
of a husband, a man...
Not now, Doctor.
Please.
Bridge to Riker, urgent.
Riker here.
Sir, regret to inform you
that the Captain
appears to be infected.
And Data.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
I'm on my way.
You'll have
to handle this.
Are you saying
you're going to handle that?
( alarm blaring )
WORF:
What we're
seeing, sir
is a huge chunk of the star's
surface blown away--
heading for us.
Take us...
Are you all right, sir?
Worf...
you do know
what to do.
Take us...
Take us out of here.
Right.
The controls
are still off-line, sir.
Override.
Same result, sir.
RIKER:
Wes, come in, please.
Wesley Crusher, this is Riker.
This is urgent. Come in, please.
Engineering, urgent.
We must have ship's power.
These are control chips.
Bridge from Engineering.
The star is
still collapsing.
We're directly in the path.
I can't help you, Bridge.
Someone here has yanked out
all the control chips.
It was an adult who did it.
Sir, I estimate 14 minutes
until that mass gets here.
No way, sir. I cannot replace
these chips in 14 minutes.
Two hours...
three, maybe.
Data could assemble
them back faster.
PICARD:
What?
What's that?
What's that, Wesley?
Well, they're just simple
isolinear chips, sir.
To Data, anyway.
He could shuffle them
like cards.
Come on, Data. Hurry!
Ship's Log,
First Officer Riker:
Enterprise will be destroyed
unless it can be moved
out of the path
of the star material
hurtling toward us.
Our only hope is for
Lieutenant Commander Data
in the time we have left,
to regain his senses
and reconnect engine power
to the Bridge.
Nice to see
you, Wesley.
Hi, Mr. Data.
No time for courtesy.
Get the damned
control chips back in place
in the correct order. Now!
It's like a game of
"How fast can you do it?"
Ah, a game.
( alarm sounding )
I think I can switch this
to main viewer, sir.
Data, we have eight or
nine minutes at most.
Can you finish by then?
No. This will take slightly
more time than we have, sir.
Oh, damn it, no! I can't
afford to get this.
Beverly.
Yes, Jean-Luc?
You will address
me as Captain.
( laughs ):
Captain?
Well, then, my dear Captain
you will address me as
Chief Medical Officer or Doctor.
I will?
That's true.
I started out by
calling you Beverly
and, of course,
naturally, you...
I'm still not
thinking straight.
Likewise. Where the hell
was I headed?
If that's something you
were going to test...
Yes, on Geordi!
Come here.
( alarm sounding )
See how I reversed the fields
on this, Commander?
I made it into
a repulser beam.
If we just had
one minute more, sir.
If this were a hundred times
more powerful than it is...
Why not try it
with the real thing?
Why not reverse fields on this,
Ma'am?
If we just need an extra minute.
It would take weeks
of laying out new circuits.
Why not just see it
in your head?
Come off the main lead
split off at the force activator
then... then...
if I could just
think straight about this.
I made this a broader-based
remedy--
I hope.
But it's still very close
to the formula
from the old Enterprise
records.
Decades ago,
light-years away...
BEVERLY:
But almost exactly the
same conditions as here.
Wow! What was
in that, Doctor?
My head's beginning
to clear.
Come here.
Here, take this
to Engineering.
I'll make up hypos
for the others.
Okay...
Bev.
( alarm sounding )
We're not going
to make it, Captain.
If we only had
a minute or so more.
Yes, then reversing power leads
back through the force activator
repulser beam hard
against Tsiolkovsky.
WESLEY:
Don't you see?
It's giving us a push-off,
the extra time we need.
We're pushing away.
Bridge, engage engines.
Captain, something seemed
to move us aside
at the last minute.
Do we owe our thanks
to Commander Data, sir?
PICARD:
Yes, and Wesley may have given
us a few seconds, too.
Did he say Wesley--
the boy?
He said Wesley.
It's only fair to mention
Wesley in a log entry, sir.
Fair is fair.
And let's credit
his science teacher, too.
Congratulations, sir.
To many people.
Data.
I'm only going to tell
you this just once--
it never happened.
I put it to you all--
I think we shall end up
with a fine crew
if we avoid temptation.
So, Number One
let's go to
our next job.
Aye, sir.
Helm, prepare
for warp 3.
Heading 294, mark 37.
Warp 3, heading 294,
mark 37, sir.
Engage.