Captain's Log,
Stardate 41235.25:
Our location, planet Ligon II,
source of a rare vaccine needed
on Federation planet Styris
IV.
Starfleet has instructed me
to engage in a friendly visit
and open treaty negotiations
to acquire
this medicinal substance.
Standard orbit, sir.
Lieutenant Yar calling
from Cargo Bay 1, sir.
Standing by to beam the Ligonian
welcoming party aboard.
On our way.
You have the helm, Mr. Data.
Cargo 1.
This should be
an interesting experience.
Agreed.
Not only are they
closely humanoid,
but their history has
remarkable similarities to ours.
A highly-
structured society,
and they're
exceedingly proud.
They've insisted
on using their own
transporter device, sir.
It's their way,
Lieutenant.
Do they have
our coordinates?
They have, sir,
precisely,
and they're standing by
for your signal.
This is
Captain Picard
aboard the Starfleet
vessel Enterprise.
Please do us the honor
of visiting our vessel.
I am Lutan.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
Welcome aboard.
These are
my officers.
My second
in command,
Commander
William Riker...
ship's counselor,
Deanna Troi...
and my
security officer,
Lieutenant
Natasha Yar.
A woman?
Your chief
of security?
Yes, Lutan.
That is her
expertise.
I am honored to
meet your officers.
This is my secondary, Hagon.
A sample of the vaccine.
My duty, Lutan.
I'm sorry,
but I'm required
to inspect...
Out of my way, woman!
How interesting.
May we prove as surprising
to you.
( chuckles )
If I may suggest, sir...
no apology.
In their view,
it would weaken us.
Nothing concealed,
Captain.
Would you care
to accept it?
Unless you care to
examine it further.
Absolutely not.
This vaccine sample
is a gift of life,
and we are honored
at receiving it.
Would you do us
the additional honor now
of letting us
entertain you?
Yes, yes,
please prepare it.
We shall join you shortly.
I ask forgiveness.
They are strange
alien things.
You bear no fault.
But the female...
May be exactly
what I have needed.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Lutan, we are aware of many
of your planet's achievements
and its unique similarity
to an ancient Earth
culture we all admire.
On behalf of the
Federation, therefore
I would like to
present this token
of our gratitude
and friendship.
From China's
Sung Dynasty,
14th century.
13th century, sir.
Ah, yes, indeed.
A most thoughtful gift.
We are pleased.
We of Ligon
have been
apprehensive
about strangers.
We are not as technologically
advanced as you,
yet we possess
something you do not--
a vaccine which has been found
to be an effective antidote
against your dreaded
Anchilles fever.
If you respect
our customs
and we see
that respect,
we will be friends,
and we will make the antidote
available to all who need it.
If you require
respect from us,
I'm sure that
you will see it.
( chuckles )
Surrounded by
such friendship,
I feel no need
for my guards.
I will return shortly.
Prepare to transport me then.
PICARD:
If there is anything else,
any further
courtesy...
Would it be possible
to see one of your
wondrous holodecks?
We have heard how they are
used to train your officers.
And used for many
other things, too.
Commander Riker,
perhaps you and
Counselor Troi
would demonstrate.
Would it be possible
for Lieutenant Yar to do so,
Captain?
Some demonstration
of defense training?
We've noticed you're intrigued
with her having
security responsibilities.
But these things are not
at all unusual with us.
With us, it is the duty
of women only to own the land
and the duty of
men to protect...
and rule it.
Much the same has
happened
in human history, too.
I'd like to do it, sir...
as a sign of respect,
perhaps.
PICARD:
Very well.
This way, please.
Aikido, one.
It won't move again
until my actions activate it.
You can create people
without a soul?
It's not a real
person, Lutan.
It has no life.
Everything it does is
controlled by computer.
Who am I?
Do you hear me?
But it will feel real
when it hits you.
A force like that
cannot possibly
come from an image,
Lutan.
Then you will
show me, Hagon.
( chuckling )
Thank you, Lieutenant.
How very enlightening.
Aikido, vanish.
I could create
two... even three,
but, really,
one is enough.
As you fight with it,
it learns, and before long
it knows exactly
how to defeat you.
Even the extraordinary
Lieutenant Yar?
It forces us to
keep improving.
Your skill...
impresses me.
I like you.
Farewell, my new friends
of the noble Enterprise.
Understanding has made friends
of many different people.
We've had a good
beginning, Lutan.
May I also extend a personal
farewell to Lieutenant Yar
in your Federation terms?
( gasps )
Picard to Bridge.
Red alert!
( alarm sounding )
Shields up. Photon torpedoes
activated, sir.
What com contact
do we have with them?
With their orbital
control station, sir.
Make contact there
and on all hailing frequencies.
This is the Enterprise to Lutan
and the Ligonian government.
You have committed
an unfriendly act.
We insist that
you reply immediately.
Photon torpedoes ready, sir.
Set them for a display blast
a thousand meters short
of the planet surface.
Set.
Fire.
Do we know the source
of their transporter beam?
Our own transporter people
have tried to trace it, sir,
but to no effect.
It reads similar
to early Starfleet efforts
but uses the Heglenian shift
to convert energy and
matter in different...
which is actually not
important at this time.
This is Captain Picard
of the Enterprise
with a message to Lutan
whom I have so far
acknowledged as a friend.
But you have now committed
what our laws regard
as an attack upon us.
Since you have
visited our vessel,
you most certainly
know the power of it.
We insist that you reply
to this message.
Opinion, Counselor.
Will they injure Lieutenant Yar?
I believe not, sir.
They seem mainly curious.
In the case of Lutan, however
I did feel other needs.
What kind of needs?
Some sexual attraction
from all the males.
Lieutenant Yar is
physically very attractive.
But with Lutan,
I felt something else.
Something more like
avarice
or ambition.
Other comments?
If I may, sir?
One of the things about them
in the briefing studies
was their respect
for patience.
Strongly emphasized.
And you can see it
in the precise,
ritualistic way
they do things.
I'm worried about
Lieutenant Yar, too, sir.
But maybe we should sit
and wait them out.
PICARD:
Stardate 41235.32:
I am concerned.
Over a full day of waiting
with no response from Lutan.
We are now testing
whether they are aware
of our sensors
probing them.
So far, we believe we have
pinpointed Lutan's
government compound.
The vaccine, sir.
Yes, Doctor?
The vaccine.
I'm a physician--
I've seen death--
but not on the scale
this could mean.
You were testing if you
can replicate the vaccine.
And we can't.
The sample works fine
when used as an injection
but becomes unstable
when we try to replicate it.
You must get the vaccine
from the planet, Captain,
as much as you can,
immediately.
I'm aware of that, Doctor.
You've never had to watch
a patient die from this disease.
That's true.
But I have seen
my share of death.
( sighs )
Damn!
Where are the calluses
we doctors are supposed
to grow over our feelings?
Perhaps the good ones
never get them.
May I speak to you
about my son, Wesley?
What?
Oh. Yes.
All right.
He seems quite interested
in starship operations
and, speaking as
a mother, of course,
he seems
quite knowledgeable.
Well, yes...
speaking as a mother.
He's on the turbolift.
You'll remember you ordered him
to stay off of the Bridge.
Wesley.
I haven't
stepped one foot
on your Bridge, Captain.
All right, sir, I'll see
that he leaves immediately.
No.
No?
Why don't you sit at Ops
next to Lieutenant La Forge?
Sir?
Is the whole ship deaf?
Sit down over there,
young man.
PICARD:
Temporarily.
Captain, we have
more information
from the briefing studies
on Ligon.
Oh, excuse me.
Dr. Crusher, some of
this may interest you.
Let's hear
the analysis.
It is a highly
structured society
in which people live by
strict codes of honor.
For example, what Lutan did
is similar to what certain
American Indians once did
called "counting coup."
That is from an obscure
language known as French.
DATA:
"Counting coup..."
Mr. Data,
the French language
for centuries on Earth
represented civilization.
Indeed?
But surely, sir...
I suggest you drop it,
Mr. Data.
Yes, sir.
"Counting coup" could be
something as simple as
touching an enemy
with a stick in battle
or taking something
from him and escaping.
It was considered
extremely heroic.
And under
these circumstances,
Lutan considers
himself heroic,
risking literally
everything
in the face of
our superior power.
And it fits Lutan's
personality profile as well.
He has an abnormally high
need for achievement.
Self-image to him
is a function
of what he thinks
he's achieved.
Those who set their
standards too high
can kill to meet them.
Why Tasha?
As a Starfleet
security officer,
she may have represented
his riskiest prize.
( control buzzes )
Transmission from
planet surface, sir.
DATA:
Main viewer on.
PICARD:
Well, Lutan, what do you want?
You will display
your image, please.
What is required
is an image
of Lieutenant Yar,
well and...
Are you making demands,
Captain?
Sir.
( control beeps )
According to the Ligon
code of honor,
Lutan has done
what he set out to do:
achieve recognition
for being daring and bold.
We've studied this
in some depth now, sir.
The proper thing
for you to do now
is to ask to
get Tasha back.
Ask for her?
Politely, Captain.
( control beeps )
And now, Lutan,
you have boldly taken
Lieutenant Yar from us,
and we ask that...
that you now
please return her.
Then come visit us,
Captain,
and we shall
return her to you.
Commander.
"Commander"?
That's quite formal.
So is this
request, sir.
We believe it
would be preferable
if the Captain led
this away party.
Agreed, sir.
Their customs concerning guests
make it much preferable.
And I'm very much
against that idea.
Lutan is clearly
a liar and devious.
Counselor Troi has admitted
that she believes
he's capable of killing.
It is my duty is to keep
the Captain from danger, sir.
Except that Ligonian custom
makes it clear
that a visiting leader
becomes an honored guest.
Not us.
Not second
in command.
Him.
And the custom requires
that Lutan should die
rather than violate that.
Yes, it seems reasonable,
put that way.
But I warn you,
if you get hurt,
I'll put you on report, Captain.
Welcome to my centerplace,
Captain Picard.
Consider yourselves
my honored guests.
Every hospitality
will be accorded you.
This is my first one:
Yareena.
PICARD:
Lutan is a fortunate man.
You've met Counselor Troi.
Yes. As on your vessel,
you have only to name whatever
courtesy we can provide.
Then, sir, the courtesy
of seeing Lieutenant Yar.
Lieutenant Yar will be
returned to you tonight
at a banquet I have arranged
in your honor.
I'd like to see her now.
Bring Lieutenant Yar.
I find it odd,
Captain,
that a man of
your experience
has such difficulty
in understanding
ordinary politeness.
Such as the politeness
of saying "please"
before abducting someone?
The expression "please" is used
only when requesting
the person back.
Yours is a different world.
With clear and simple ways
deeply rooted in our culture.
If you are
willing to...
ask for
Lieutenant Yar's return
tonight in front of all,
honor will be
satisfied.
One can see
the importance
of honor here, sir.
Honor is everything.
( Yar grunting )
Have you been treated
well, Lieutenant?
Fine, Captain.
But they're showing
some signs of wear.
There isn't any need
to be concerned, Captain.
She's been well cared for.
My ship's company
and I are certain
of your gentle
wisdom in that.
For a moment, I thought
I heard a threat implied.
But that would be
foolishness.
Something to be carefully
avoided, I agree.
The festivities for her return
to you are in preparation.
Shall we retire till then?
Until tonight, Lutan.
( rhythmic tapping )
Lutan, you have granted us
hospitality
and the safety
of your centerplace.
The gifts you give us are
rare and precious.
We thank you.
And now,
according to the customs
of your ancestors,
whom we honor
and respect,
I am here in peace
to ask for the return
of Lieutenant Yar.
Well-spoken.
There are those among my equals
in this gathering who were wary
of my approaching
the Federation.
I am proud
to have taken
this first step
toward a treaty
and proud that we have something
of great value to offer you.
A priceless,
life-giving vaccine.
The abduction I have done
according to our custom
for all to see.
Your conduct in this matter
has been beyond exemplary,
Captain Picard.
But now that
the moment has come...
I find that I cannot part
with her.
( all gasp and murmur )
You speak of a code of honor.
What you are saying now
according to our customs
is called an act of war.
This is not an act of war
but of love.
I want Lieutenant Yar
to become my first one.
I challenge your right
of supersedence!
No woman has challenged
supersedence for over 200 years.
The right is mine,
and I will have it.
Natasha Yar,
I challenge you.
A struggle to the death.
No!
The challenge is
unequivocally refused.
Then you shall have
no treaty, no vaccine,
and no Lieutenant Yar!
Ship's Log,
First Officer Riker reporting:
We've been informed of the
challenge to Lieutenant Yar
and are maintaining combat
readiness around the clock.
We are probing Lutan's compound
deeply with our sensors now,
still unnoticed.
Captain. Deanna.
Did you have any idea,
Lieutenant,
that Lutan was suddenly
going to announce
that he wanted you
for his first one?
No, sir.
Tell me what you
know about this.
Nothing, sir.
But it was a thrill.
Lutan is such...
such a basic
male image,
and having him say
he wants you...
Yes, of course it made me
feel good when he...
Troi, I'm your friend,
and you tricked me!
Only so you'd think about it,
completely and clearly.
We're all being
manipulated, Lieutenant.
Myself most of all.
How simple all this would be
without the Prime Directive.
That thought had passed
through my mind, Counselor.
What is this message
from Starbase 14?
It's showing the
infection rates--
percentage
illness increases.
Plague on Styris IV has
flared up out of control.
LA FORGE:
They're estimating deaths
in the millions, sir.
Captain Picard,
come in.
I know I can win--
not that I'd take
her life, of course--
but I'd be glad
to embarrass her.
The idea of accusing me
of taking...
The plague?
If anything, even worse
than we'd heard.
Which means they desperately
need the vaccine, sir.
And I know I can
win this challenge.
You have nothing to prove here,
Lieutenant.
But the vaccine is important
in this case, sir.
Counselor, you're the last
person I'd expect to argue
in favor of accepting
the challenge.
Betazoid blood is also
practical, Captain.
The odds are very good she'd
defeat Lutan's wife easily,
and you would win all the
bargaining points you need.
"The odds are..."
You have pointed
out yourself,
we are all at risk.
every day of
every mission.
I want some explanation
from Lutan.
Lutan, why are you obsessed
with this Lieutenant Yar?
Surely Yareena is
more desirable.
Certainly she can
offer you much more.
She owns many things,
many lands.
It's a great pity
you began by abducting
my security officer, Lutan,
because,
I should tell you,
I do admire
the hospitality
you offer here.
I am in the grip of forces
you do not understand.
Some of it
I do understand.
She's a rather
lovely female.
( chuckles )
You surprise me, Captain.
What do you know
of needs and feelings?
Nothing.
Well, almost nothing--
in my position
as ship's Captain.
( chuckles )
I see.
But it puzzles me.
If you feel like that
for Tasha,
why have you challenged her
to a fight to the death?
Not I; Yareena.
I am merely a spectator.
Ah, but you are also a man
of great importance and wealth.
Great importance, perhaps,
but he doe...
I see.
You too understand
the proper value of women.
We understand that they are
highly pleasant things
but, after all,
unimportant--
except for
the land they own.
You are a truly clever
person, Lutan.
You stand to
lose nothing
either way the
challenge goes.
A code of honor protects one,
Captain, like a magic cloak.
I will order
Lieutenant Yar to fight.
And may your cloak
bring you...
all you deserve.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Why that razor, my friend?
Why not the one I adjusted
to perfect efficiency?
Shaving is a human
art form, Data.
Technological perfection
can shave too close.
Puzzling.
How can anything be
too efficient?
Thousands of things
are too efficient, Data,
at least for humans.
We always come back
to the human equation.
Exactly.
Have you continued
to work on it?
Constantly,
my friend...
particularly
the humor.
A man goes to a store
to buy some kidneys.
Oh, no...
He says
to the shopkeeper,
"I'd like a pound of
kiddillies, please."
The shopkeeper says, "You
mean kidneys, don't you?"
The man says, "I said
kiddillies, diddle I?"
It's too old,
and you didn't
tell it very well.
How do you know when
something is funny?
It's not explainable.
You... you just do.
Perhaps it is you,
Geordi.
Includle-ing
the kiddillies,
I've told 662 jokes,
and you've not...
"Includling
the kiddillies"!
Now, see, that's funny.
( laughing )
It was not meant
as a joke.
( laughing harder )
The tongue slipped.
Oh... oh boy.
( over com ):
Riker to Commander Data,
Lieutenant La Forge.
Report to the transporter room
for away-party duty.
First Officer to Captain.
Ready with the away personnel.
Lock in on
this location.
Transporter
locked in, sir.
Energize.
You've both seen
the message about
the plague?
And how badly the vaccine
is needed, yes, sir.
We need to know
as much as possible
about Ligonian armaments.
Data, especially
important is
an analysis of their
combat capabilities.
Geordi, concentrate
on their cutting edges
wherever applicable--
durability, composition,
weaknesses of material.
Aye, sir.
From any particular
point of view, sir?
From the perspective
of Lieutenant Yar
using them in combat
with Lutan's wife.
Most interesting.
Could this be
human joke number 663?
Negative, Data.
That's a Captain's order.
Which makes it
important to know
which of these weapons
are to be used.
And that won't be known
until combat begins.
You're right, Data.
It does sound
like a joke.
With the power
of the Enterprise,
we could overwhelm
this place easily,
just take what we want.
I may not understand
human humor, sir,
but I am a Starfleet
Academy graduate.
Which means,
of course...
Understanding
the Prime Directive, sir.
( sighs )
And that is, ironically,
what this is about.
By our standards,
the customs here,
their... code of honor
is the same kind of
pompous, strutting charades
that endangered our own species
a few centuries ago.
We evolved out of it
because no one tried
to impose
their own set of...
I'm sorry, this is
becoming a speech.
You are
the Captain, sir.
You're entitled.
Mm, not entitled
to ramble on about
something everyone knows.
Carry on.
Ship's Log, Commander William
Riker reporting:
Continuing our appraisal
of Ligonian technology.
The Captain has made it clear
he wants Lieutenant Yar
beamed immediately
to safety
if her life should
become endangered.
And I fervently hope
the rules
of that contest
make it possible.
Riker to Transporter Chief.
Do we have our people
on sensors yet?
Their general area, sir,
visual on screen now.
As you see, we're still
doing some fine tuning.
I've agreed
to this meeting,
but I see no point to it.
You've accepted
the challenge,
and there is nothing
further to say.
I think you should
know that there is
no physical training anywhere
that matches Starfleet,
especially
its security people.
And you should
know that,
even though these
contests are rare,
we have a tradition of making
ourselves capable of them.
Yareena...
my acceptance had
nothing to do with Lutan.
It has everything
to do with Lutan!
Lutan wants you
to be his first one.
Impossible, Yareena.
I am a career
Starfleet officer.
How could you not love him?
Every woman loves him.
I fight for
the vaccine.
That's the truth.
The truth...
is I will kill you
if I can.
And believe me, I can.
There's nothing else
to say.
In my world,
it's a greater honor
to refuse...
You are on our world!
Captain, I'm
your counselor.
You brought me with you
to Ligon to be of help.
Then help me, please.
What is a way
out of this?
With the vaccine?
Mm-hmm.
None.
The weapons in
that room, Captain,
are surprisingly flexible,
durable, and deadly.
And light, as if they were
made for women to use.
Mm. Some of them still have
traces of blood and poison.
Poison?
Mm.
Alkaloid base.
Lethal.
What about those lengths of
metal in the yard outside?
Uncertain, sir.
However,
joined together,
they would make
a rectangle or square
enclosing
121 square meters.
If put end to end
vertically,
they would make a pole
44 meters high--
or two of 22.
Thank you, Data.
You're welcome, sir.
She won't budge.
She loves him,
without reservation.
And she thinks
I love him, too.
Most interesting.
Do you?
Of course I don't, Data.
As Troi pointed out to me,
I'm attracted to him,
but that's
entirely different.
( over com ):
Riker to Captain.
Go ahead, Riker.
We're alone.
We're fine-tuned enough
to see your hosts
gathering in the open area
outside, sir.
Three of them are heading
for your location.
Thank you,
Number One.
Lieutenant, you still
feel that you want
to go through with
this challenge?
You judge your
condition good?
I judge it excellent, sir.
Your weapons,
Lieutenant Yar.
You may choose
your size.
Tasha, don't
touch the spines.
They're poisoned.
If you're not careful,
you could kill yourself.
These I understand.
( Yareena grunting )
( physical training sounds )
( grunting )
( sizzling )
First Officer's Log,
supplemental:
Captain Picard,
faced with a critical need
for a vaccine produced
on this planet
has permitted
Lieutenant Natasha Yar
to engage in a fight
to the death.
I have yet to understand
his reasoning or his plan.
Care to lend a hand?
Sit at Ops.
Was I seen leaving?
They've got eyes
only for the program.
Captain Picard
wanted no risk
of our communication
being overheard.
You are to proceed
now, as he indicated.
Captain's orders, too.
Did the Captain
understand
what you and Geordi reported
about these weapons?
They're razor-sharp,
split-second lethal?
I'm here to brief you
on what he plans.
( rhythmic tapping )
Any last-minute
instructions, sir?
Stay alive.
We'll hope
to do the rest.
( crowd shouting and murmuring)
I speak for Lutan.
The rules are known.
Let combat continue
until there is a victor.
It will not be interrupted.
( cheering )
Combatants!
Hold your positions.
Return the weapon.
Careful, Yareena!
( all gasp )
Move!
We're too late.
She's growing cold.
Sorry, that clashes
with my instructions.
No, no... no, no.
( sighs )
Exactly what do you
find unfair, Lutan?
They fought
to the death.
You saw the
final blow.
You know the effects
of your poison.
But what of your
Lieutenant Yar?
She is to become
my first one now.
I certainly
won't stop her
if she cares to
claim that honor.
Remember, you have
all Yareena's wealth
and lands, Lutan.
( chuckles )
At least all
has not been lost.
( over com ):
Riker to Captain.
Picard here.
Since you've fulfilled
your agreement, Captain,
can we now beam
the vaccine aboard?
Ah, yes, of course.
No problem, Number One.
Send down a medical team.
And to complete
our business here--
we're locked onto you.
Five to beam up.
Energize.
Welcome back,
Captain.
You're wanted
in the lounge.
This way, gentlemen.
She is not dead!
There was no death combat.
You violated
our agreement.
There will be no treaty,
no vaccine.
The challenge was
carried out.
She died, Lutan.
There was no challenge.
She lives!
I am a physician
and saw her die.
If you doubt this poison,
why don't you test
it on yourself?
Lutan, we can
provide you
with records of her death
and how Dr. Crusher
brought her back.
And at the instant
of death, Lutan,
a mating agreement dissolves.
But this is witchcraft,
Yareena.
To discard a mate
in this manner...
Is less painful than the one
you selected for me.
Yareena, no.
Even as I battled,
Hagon,
I heard you
calling out for me.
Yareena, be
my first one.
All my land
and all my goods--
all I have is yours
to rule.
How sad for you.
You've lost everything.
I have my honor.
It's... such a waste.
Do you want him?
No.
There would...
be complications.
Then I will have you
as my number two.
Take your place,
accordingly.
Well, as you see,
Captain, you may
excel in technology
but not in
civilized behavior.
What...?
PICARD:
Wesley?
Yeah, Wesley,
he'd been manning
that station for me,
I forgot.
Well...
thanks again for manning one
of our Bridge stations, Wesley.
We'll see...
that you have
another chance.
Yes, sir.
So what's the delay,
Number One?
Why aren't we warping
out of here?
Set course
for Styris IV, warp 3.
Course laid in
for Styris IV, sir.
Engage.