Captain's Log,
Stardate 41386.4:
We are in pursuit of a starship
of Ferengi design.
Our mission is
to intercept and recover
a T-9 energy converter
which the Ferengi stole
from an unmanned monitor post
on Gamma Tauri IV
a theft which automatic
scanners recorded
providing us with
the long-awaited opportunity
to make close contact
with a Ferengi vessel.
If we succeed in this chase
it will be Starfleet's
first look at a life-form
which, discounting rumor,
we know almost nothing about.
There she is.
Enlarge.
What is their course?
They're now angling through
that solar system, Captain.
Identify.
Listed as
Delphi Ardu, sir--
eleven planets,
unexplored.
Stay with them, La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Sensors read a power surge
from their last maneuver,
Captain.
LA FORGE:
They are dropping
to sub-warp speed.
Reduce to impulse power.
Sensors record fluctuations
in the energy readings from it,
Captain.
Possibility:
a malfunction in
their engines, sir.
Breaks my heart.
WORF:
In visual range,
Captain.
Fully enlarge.
Hello, stranger.
Very impressive design.
Anything on that
design, Data?
Nothing specific, sir.
As you know,
Ferengi technology
is estimated to be
generally equal
to our own.
PICARD:
But that does not mean
identical, however.
Correct, sir.
We are no doubt
advanced in some areas--
they in others.
Showing another
power surge, sir.
They are firing on us!
Damage report.
YAR:
Shields holding.
Mostly electromagnetic.
Fusion generator
and batteries
down by 30 percent.
Our impulse engines
are surging now.
WORF:
They're
firing again.
YAR:
Deflector shield power
weakening, Captain.
Phasers ready.
Photon torpedoes ready.
Do we return their fire, sir?
Negative,
Number One.
They're just responding
to our close pursuit.
Fall back a bit,
but stay with them.
They're slowing too, sir.
They may be turning to fight.
Open hailing frequen...
Why are we gaining on them?
Don't anticipate.
LA FORGE:
I'm not, sir.
Something's wrong.
DATA:
Sir, something is
dragging us forward.
I read that, too.
Lieutenant Yar, what
do your sensors show?
Not certain, sir.
I'm getting
very confusing readings.
Captain...
this shouldn't be.
Our power systems
are failing.
YAR:
Deflector
shield failing.
Phasers going inoperative,
Captain.
Captain, something is completely
immobilizing us.
Immobilized by the damn Ferengi!
I need more
information.
What the hell
are they using?
Obviously, we've
underestimated
their technology,
Captain.
Considerably.
It appears the Ferengi have us
right where they want us--
in their sights.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Are you searching
all frequencies?
Is there any sign
of any message?
Negative, sir.
Weapons report, Lieutenant.
I have phasers
and torpedoes armed
but I show insufficient power
to fire them.
Engineering, give me status
on power recovery.
Engineering, come in.
Why aren't they
answering?
La Forge.
Sir?
Get me a full report
from Engineering.
Aye, sir.
It's impossible
they could be draining
all power
from all systems.
Counselor?
I'm sensing nothing
from them, sir.
Which could mean
they can shield
their thoughts and emotions
from others.
Which still makes it
our move.
Sir, they may know as little
about us as we do about them.
Except that they know that
they've got us in deep trouble.
If so, then
the question becomes
what do they do
with that knowledge?
Data, do you have
any information
touching this on any file?
None, sir.
Only hearsay
and third-hand reports
most of which conflict.
Which reports
do not conflict?
That the Ferengi are...
Well, the best description
may be "traders."
What kind of traders?
A comparison modern scholars
have drawn from Earth history
likens the Ferengi to
the ocean-going Yankee traders
of 18th and 19th century
America, sir.
From the history
of my forebears--
Yankee traders.
Who in this case sail the galaxy
in search of mercantile
and territorial opportunity.
And are these scholars
saying that
the Ferengi
may not be unlike us?
Hardly, sir.
I believe the analogy refers
to the worst quality
of capitalists.
The Ferengi are believed
to conduct their affairs
of commerce
on the ancient principle,
caveat emptor--
"let the buyer beware."
RIKER:
Yankee traders--
I like the sound of that.
Well, sir...
I doubt they wear
red, white and blue
or look anything like Uncle Sam.
Engineering?
Join La Forge down below
in Engineering, Number One.
Aye, sir.
Without warp capacity,
we're just a floating target.
Uncle who?
YAR:
What have bright
primary colors
got to do with it?
I understand the allusion.
Colors representing countries
at a time when they
competed with each other.
Red, white and blue
for the United States
whereas the French more properly
used the same colors
in the order
of blue, white and red.
And the German nation
red, black and gold
the Italians green, white
and red; the British...
That's enough, Data.
It was you who...
We were discussing
the Ferengi.
I wish I had some clue
as to what they
will do next.
Given what is now happening
to our ship, sir
their weapons could be
vastly superior to ours.
Yes, Data, that is
a natural assumption.
Engineering?
Bottom line, La Forge.
Uh, it's not good, sir.
The Ferengi force field
that holds this ship
compensates almost as fast
as we can increase power.
Almost?
Well, there's a .372
millisecond delay
between the use
of our power
and the neutralizing counter
force of the Ferengi.
See, we push and they push back
with equal force, sir.
What's our acceleration delay
between slow-reverse impulse
and top warp speed?
Well, that's .300 milliseconds,
but there's...
Ah, I see
where you're going.
We shift down then kick hard
into warp nine.
Yeah, come back
fighting! Whoo-whee!
Can we do it, Geordi?
Ask me after
it's done, sir.
I want a slow reverse-engine
drop-off over five minutes.
We'll show them
what this baby can do, sir.
Give me everything
you've got, La Forge.
Aye, aye, sir.
RIKER:
Now a sudden abrupt power surge
to high warp speed, Captain
we may be able to break loose
from that Ferengi force field.
I wish I knew what they
were thinking over there.
They're wondering what
we're going to do next.
I say fight, sir.
There's nothing shameful
in falling
before a superior enemy.
And nothing shameful
in a strategic retreat either.
LA FORGE:
All systems
ready, Captain.
And communication
now restored to engineering.
Excellent, La Forge.
Now, let's uh...
Let's throw them
off guard.
Lieutenant Yar,
open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
At least we won't begin
with weakness.
Attention,
Ferengi starship.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
In the name of the United
Federation of Planets
I demand that you return
the T-9 energy converter
you removed from Gamma Tauri IV.
Send that in all language forms.
All language forms, sir.
Sometimes, Riker
the best way to fight
is not to be there.
Yes, sir.
"He will triumph
who knows when to fight
and when not to fight."
I'm glad the Academy
is still teaching
the strategies of Sun Tzu.
This delay had better
prove out, La Forge.
.300 milliseconds, sir.
Let's blast full power
into warp nine.
Ready?
On your command, Captain.
On the count of three.
Stand by on phasers.
One-- set warp to nine.
Two-- divert shield power
to main engines.
Three.
Merde.
Shields up.
Captain, I think
you had better see this.
What's wrong?
Someone is reading
every file
every bit of information
stored in the Enterprise
memory banks.
They can do that?
And more, perhaps.
Captain.
If I may
recommend.
With our attention
on the Ferengi vessel
we have ignored the planet.
Data, consult the charts
on this planet.
See what we've got on it.
Conference evaluation.
So, while we still have
some power left
it's time
for difficult decisions.
Opinions, please?
I say put all available power
into a full-out, combined phaser
and photon torpedo salvo.
Destroy their ability to sustain
this force field, sir.
Yes!
Hit them hard and hit them fast.
Impractical.
And provocative.
Even assuming that we have the
power to sustain such a tactic.
But, Captain, isn't firing on us
an act of war?
TROI:
The facts are the Ferengi
did fire on us
but we were
chasing them.
Since then, all they've done
is search our computers
trying to learn
who and what we are.
Your point, Counselor?
Let's talk to them.
It's been tried.
No response.
But did we tell them
anything they wanted to hear?
La Forge?
Other opinions?
Thank you for your advice.
PICARD:
Will...
I haven't heard your assessment.
I believe we've covered
every available option, Captain.
Are there other options
that you want to analyze?
The only one remaining
is the one that needs
no conversation--
the one we must avoid.
Sir?
The one that leads
to total annihilation.
Open hailing
frequencies.
DATA:
Open, sir.
Attention, Ferengi starship.
This is Captain Picard.
It is obvious that
we are in a situation here
which needs resolving
and we are willing to do
whatever is... required.
Whatever is necessary.
I would like...
I would request
that you present
your terms to us.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41386.5:
It is with a heavy heart
that I have offered to meet
whatever reasonable and
necessary terms are demanded
by the Ferengi.
I fear for my people
and my vessel in the event
the unknown Ferengi
ask the unreasonable.
How can I oppose
even unreasonable demands?
It's moving, sir.
WORF:
We ask to
surrender
and now they
fire on us?
Ready torpedoes, sir.
We have enough power
for a few of them.
Ready.
But hold on ready.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
Ferengi vessel,
we await your response.
Suggest first strike, sir.
Our shields now only have
63 seconds
of power left before lowering.
WORF:
If the Ferengis' ship
sensors can read us, sir
they will be waiting until
we are most vulnerable.
I'm afraid I agree, Captain;
they have not responded...
We will wait a bit more,
Number One.
50 Seconds.
Patience.
The quicker we can come
to terms
the better, NCC 1701-D.
Who is speaking?
I am Tarr,
Daimon of the Ferengi.
You wished to discuss surrender,
Captain Picard?
What I said, Daimon Tarr, is...
Unconditional surrender,
I warn you
is totally unacceptable.
We will die
to the last one of us
before such dishonor.
Hailing frequencies
closed, sir.
Something has seized
their ship, too.
They're in the same
predicament as us.
Launch a sensor probe.
Set it to search
for the source of...
whatever this "something" is
that is holding both ships.
Go back
to hailing frequency, fast.
...and I regret, Daimon Tarr,
that I can no longer negotiate
unless it is conducted visually.
Your complete message
not received, Enterprise
but visual communication
is against our custom.
And it is against
Starfleet orders
to accept
a surrender otherwise.
Do you withdraw
your surrender?
You give us
no choice, Enterprise.
May we have
a visual on you, as well?
Agreed, Daimon Tarr.
You should be able
to view us now.
Are we on your screen?
Yes, the ugliness of the hu-man
was not an exaggeration.
I do not know how
your twisted alien culture
has paralyzed our vessel
but I concede
your Enterprise is superior.
We will return
your worthless T-9 device
and we offer the lives
of our second officers
as required by the Ferengi code.
Fortunately, Starfleet
has no such rules
involving its second officers.
Is this to your satisfaction
Picard Captain?
Your offer may be inadequate
but I will discuss it
with my staff.
Stand by
for further communication.
Matthew! Pola!
You know this area
is off-limits!
Come on, come on!
Boys will be boys, Captain.
Lieutenant, have you
launched the probe?
Aye, sir.
We should be getting
those readings soon.
If we're not
holding the Ferengi
and they're not holding us,
who the hell is?
Well, the probe will give us
some of those answers, sir.
Data!
You were going
to show us something.
As requested, Captain
library computer information
on this planet.
It has been charted
only from long-range scans.
It is class "M"
but shows no indication
of life-forms--
sentient or otherwise.
However, you may find
this of interest.
Resolving it
into our language.
The center
of a huge space federation--
a population of trillions.
Trillions?
I've never heard
the word "Tkon" before.
Understandable.
It has been extinct
for 600,000 of our...
of our years.
These...
these planets
were once...
outposts...
of that empire...
Data, what are you doing?
Apologies, Captain.
I seem to have reached
an odd functional impasse.
I am, uh...
...stuck.
Then get unstuck
and continue with the briefing.
Yes, sir.
That is what
I'm trying to do, sir
but the solution eludes me.
My hero.
( laughter )
Continue, Commander.
Intriguing.
It...
it describes
the empire
as being highly advanced
and powerful
and capable
of actually moving stars.
Stars whose planets
are their defense system.
Correct, sir.
Outposts.
The planet below
was possibly one of them.
YAR:
Excuse the interruption,
Captain
but this may be worth it.
We're now receiving
a signal from the probe.
We'll take it here.
( low whistle )
Incredible!
There's our mysterious
"something," Captain.
It is a force field
of some kind.
Reaching up from
the planet's surface.
Amazing power.
Data, what does
the legend say
about the end
of the Tkon empire?
Their sun went supernova, sir.
Could this planet
have escaped that?
This planet may have been
the most distant outpost, sir
but it shows
no life-form readings.
We should take a look at it,
Number One.
Stand by with an away team.
RIKER:
And if the Ferengi
also realize
that the force field
emanates
from the planet, sir?
Mmm. That's a complication.
Maybe we should ask them
to join us in this.
Team up with
the Ferengi, sir?
We've been ordered
to learn all we can about them.
Do you know a better way?
Data.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
In orbit of a mysterious planet
whose unexplained force field
has seized us with a power
almost beyond imagination.
If there is a solution to this
it almost certainly will involve
cooperation from the Ferengi.
Ship's power drain
is critical, Captain.
I must now shut down
our shields
to maintain
life-support systems.
Understood.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies
open, sir.
Ferengi vessel
from Enterprise.
Come in.
Your alien images
again shock us.
With regard to
the surrender
Daimon Tarr, the facts are
somewhat different.
Our own probe has already shown
us your trickery, hu-man.
We withdraw our surrender.
Agreed.
Perhaps you would agree to
a more productive relationship.
I prefer
a more profitable one, hu-man.
Yankee trader.
Explain what means
"Yankee traders."
He heard that?!
He recognizes
your interest in profit...
or is that
an incorrect assumption?
We seek only what is equitable.
What do you seek?
Why did you begin
by attacking us?
We did not attack you.
We gave chase
in order to recover
a Federation-owned
energy device...
Which we know is ours!
Your barbarous Federation
placed it on one of our planets.
On the contrary--
Gamma Tauri IV is recognized
by all civilized...
The Ferengi
are not uncivilized, hu-man!
Are you suggesting otherwise?
All I'm saying is that you
removed something
which clearly did not
belong to you.
Are you now calling us thieves?
On the contrary.
I have no wish to discuss issues
of property or of territory
while our mutual
problem remains.
Like it or not
we are both trapped
by this energy-draining
force field from the planet.
On that matter,
there can be no argument.
I would like to propose a swap.
And what is a "swap"?
It's a trade--
an exchange.
Yes, trade, hu-man.
What do you offer?
We will tell you what
we know about the planet
and in trade, you will
give us your information.
Ridiculous! How do we know
you will not withhold
information.
We must trust each other, Tarr.
( laughs )
Amusing, hu-man.
"Trust" each other?
I propose that we test
this relationship
by cooperating
in a joint exploration
of the planet's surface.
And what profit
is in this Picard Captain?
The profit, Daimon Tarr,
of saving all our lives.
We will agree,
no doubt foolishly
but you are warned that any
further trickery on your part
will be met with no mercy.
Agreed.
If you care to join us
we have a well-proven
transporter device...
We have a matter-energy
device of our own.
We will beam a science
team of three
to whatever coordinates
you propose.
Excellent, we will transmit
the information shortly.
Enterprise out.
Hailing frequencies off.
I would log that agreement
as promising, at least.
I wonder, Captain.
I'm not usually one for
distrust at first sight
but this may be
an exception.
Especially in view
of the fact
that the image he
transmitted, sir
was somehow
distorted.
I sense
the same thing, Captain.
He's hiding something.
With this power drain,
we can't delay.
Now, I'd like some
additional help
in case we run
into trouble.
Can you spare Worf?
Take him.
And be careful, Number One.
DATA:
With this power drain
we may have trouble
communicating with
the Enterprise, sir.
Understood.
Anything else?
Due to this
force field
there is presently
no way to beam us back, sir.
Oh, you had to ask.
Understood.
Energize.
( explosive thunder )
Tasha!
Data!
Geordi!
Worf!
Anybody!
Data?
What are you
doing up there?
Most intriguing, sir.
I assume a problem
of inaccurately
transmitted program
coordinates
due to the force field
around the ship, sir.
Are we alone, sir?
Unfortunately.
Let's find the others.
What do you make of these?
Crystalline.
Mostly inert.
Nothing to write home about.
Excuse me?
Slang, sir.
I did use it
correctly, did I not?
They've got to be around here
somewhere.
What's that?
What?
That!
Geordi!
Are you conscious?
Do I look conscious?
What are you doing?
I'm resting, sir.
My foot stuck--
up there!
I materialized
upside down
above the planet surface.
DATA:
Tricorder's
useless, sir.
Communication's
gone, too.
Fortunately, you
did not break...
Data?
Hmm?
Data, who's that?
Who are you?
Captain's Log, supplemental:
It is now six hours since
our away team beamed down
to the planet's surface.
On the Enterprise
our condition
is rapidly worsening.
Ordinarily,
with reserve power alone
we could maintain life support
for several months
but the force holding us
has closed down all engines
and is draining
our reserve power, too.
It's getting much,
much, much colder, sir.
How far down is
it likely to go?
A lot.
Even in orbital space
it'll get below
minus 200 degrees.
We won't have to worry much
past minus 70 or so.
Feels like that now.
Good, thank you.
LETEK:
If he moves,
kill him.
Has what
we've done
broken our agreement
with their Captain?
We will accuse
the humans
of preparing
to ambush us.
It will be our word
against theirs.
And who is more
trustworthy, Mordoc?
It looks like gold.
Tastes like gold.
RIKER:
It is gold.
( thunder crashing loudly )
( screams )
Accursed planet.
It's nothing compared
to what our Captain will do
when he finds out you've broken
our landing party agreement.
What part of
the agreement?
You appeared and
attacked us.
Are you one
of their assassins?
I am Commander William Riker,
First Officer
of the USS
Enterprise.
You have a lot
to learn.
I've got this one!
Careful, Commander,
they're much stronger than...
Pygmy cretins!
Kill them.
Hideous monsters!
No!
Good.
You've heard
of phasers.
Now, over there.
Is this a female?
A human female, Letek?
It is true.
You work with your females
arm them and force them
to wear clothing.
Sickening.
I've diverted
the reserve power
down here to
the family decks.
They'll last longest.
Is there anything else
we can do, Doctor?
Where is Wesley?
He's in our quarters.
I was tempted
to give him a sedative.
You shouldn't.
I know, but he's my son.
I love him.
He has the right
to meet death awake.
Is that a male perspective?
Rubbish.
Hold it right there.
YAR:
Stop.
Stop!
Phasers on stun.
Already set.
What's going on?
What is this?
I believe
we can deduce
these crystalline
tree-shapes
are actually energy
collectors.
Along the same principle
as that which is draining
energy from our ships.
But the Ferengi whips were
working when we first arrived.
Which means something
new has happened.
LA FORGE:
I'm finally beginning
to understand
what my eyes have been
showing me.
It's patterns of force
everywhere.
This entire planet has been
turned into a power accumulator.
And these?
It's the whole point
of this place.
I can see the planet's power
emanating from...
Commander.
PORTAL:
Be you barbarians?
Speak!
( screaming )
PORTAL:
Who meets the challenge?
Who will it be?
Him.
You have awakened
portal six-three.
Do you petition
to enter the empire?
Who asks the question?
A guardian
of the Tkon empire.
Biped, excellent.
Why would we
petition to enter
an empire that
no longer exists?
PORTAL:
Why do you attempt
this deception?
The empire is forever.
Your empire fell prey
to a supernova.
We are forever.
Data.
Please repeat
the file.
It is a matter
of record, Portal.
In the age of Makto
the central star
of the Tkon empire
destabilized...
There has never been
an age of Makto.
In fact, there
have been many ages
which have come and
passed since Makto.
This is the age
of Bastu.
I'm afraid not.
According to the Tkon use
of the galactic motionary
startime charts
after Bastu came Cimi
Xora, Makto...
Enough!
Absurdities.
You must have
been asleep, Portal
for hundreds
of thousands of our years.
Deception is
the way of the human.
We Ferengi will gladly
make a petition.
We invite
your petition.
Speak.
FERENGI:
We wish to offer
our services
to serve the Tkon empire
at no profit.
Return control
of our starship to us
and we will
happily destroy
the human criminals
and their vessel
which attacked us
without provocation.
They came to loot
your empire
but...
we intercepted them.
You are accused
of deceit and treachery.
Do you give yourself up
for judgment?
RIKER:
Yes.
If you believe these accusations
then you certainly should act
on them.
And there is even more.
We can prove
that the humans
are destroyers
of legal commerce.
And that they
selfishly withhold
vital technology
from backward worlds.
And necessary defensive
weapons, too.
We Ferengi are
now challenge
this human
madness.
I admit we withheld
modern technologies
from some worlds.
You see,
they are demented.
Their values are insane.
You cannot believe
the business opportunities
they have destroyed.
Proof of their
barbarism--
they adorn
themselves
with gold.
A despicable use of
the valuable metal.
And they
shamelessly
clothe their females.
Inviting others
to unclothe them.
The very depth
of perversion.
Paws off, Ferengi!
No female--
human or Ferengi
can order
Mordoc around.
Submit.
Just try it,
shorty.
At ease, Lieutenant.
And we still have more faults.
They should add
that Starfleet
has permitted several
civilizations to fall.
We have at times
allowed the strong
and violent to
overcome the weak.
They admit their crimes.
Hear them.
They admit the evil
that they do.
Barbarian.
Yes, you show wisdom.
Barbarians, all.
But this one first.
In the fashion
the empire has always
challenged savages.
No!
For battle, come to me!
That's an order.
PORTAL:
You have a single
chance for life.
One only.
What is the answer
to my challenge?
I offer a thought.
"He will triumph
who knows when to fight
and when not to fight."
You are being tested, Riker.
What is the answer?
How do you
know my name?
Ah...
You are facing fate
with composure.
But what is the answer
to my challenge?
Fear is the true enemy,
the only enemy.
Unlike these little ones
who close their minds
your mind holds
interesting thoughts.
"Know your enemy
and know yourself
and you will always
be victorious."
Why that thought?
And who is this Sun Tzu
you revere?
An old Chinese
philosopher
from ancient
Earth history.
You must tell me more
of this wisdom--
so much
like our own.
Gladly, but first,
our starship.
Can you release it?
It is released.
All power
is restored.
Not a moment
too soon, Jean.
I mean, Captain.
I admit, I had
my doubts
as your ships
battled each other
in overt acts
of belligerence.
Normally, I would
have destroyed
all of you
and your ships
but something
confused me.
Which was?
First, you wanted
to destroy each other
then you were willing
to assist each other.
What of our vessel?
We knew
the same answer.
The truth
is I gave
those words
to this human.
What of them?
Shall I
destroy them?
Then they would
learn nothing.
A most interesting
conclusion.
But what if they
never learn, Riker?
Is this a test also?
In life, one is
always tested.
I see them much as we were
several hundred years ago.
But possessing the technology
they now have
they're very dangerous.
Untrue.
We seek friendship
with you.
But we can hardly hate
what we once were.
They may grow and learn.
And learn ways
to destroy you.
Well, our values
require us
to face that
possibility.
What of you?
With your
empire gone?
The universe exists
to me to create life.
I shall sleep...
until needed again.
( explosive thunder )
Compliments,
Lieutenant.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Worf.
You've done well.
Something to write
home about.
"Something to write
home about"?
Data, that's very human.
The T-9 energy converter
has been beamed aboard
and secured, sir.
The Ferengi complained bitterly,
but one final roar
from Portal
convinced them.
I commend your performance,
Number One.
One final request, sir.
Permission to beam a box of
Data's Chinese finger puzzles
over to the Ferengi.
A "thank you" for all
they tried to do.
Make it so.
Set course,
La Forge.