PICARD: Captain's Log,
Stardate 41263.1:
We have rendezvoused
with the USS Fearless
from which a Starfleet
propulsion expert
and his assistant
are beaming over
to conduct tests
on the Enterprise's
warp drive engines.
They have completed
similar adjustments
on two other Starfleet vessels.
I don't understand
your concern, Number One.
They're not authorized
to make any alterations
in our engines.
According to
Starfleet's report
they will simply
run tests
on different ways of
entering warp speed
and different
intermix formulas.
Where's the
harm in that?
It's the specs
Kosinski sent us.
In my opinion, sir,
they're gibberish.
Gibberish?
Mr. Data,
would you explain?
Sir, we put Mr. Kosinski's
specs into the computer
and ran a controlled test
on them.
There was no improvement
in engine performance.
Then how do you explain
Starfleet's report
that the same tests
on the USS Ajax
and the Fearless over there
resulted in a measurable
increase in propulsion?
RIKER:
Our engines are new,
sir, top condition.
The tests on those older ships
may have simply been
to straighten out some
engine inefficiency.
MAN:
Bridge from transporter chief.
Two from USS Fearless
are ready to beam over.
Stand by for
Mr. Riker, Chief.
He's on his way.
Aye, sir.
Since you're concerned
about these tests.
Yes, sir.
Captain,
if I may
I'll ask Counselor Troi
to look these visitors over.
Very good.
Welcome aboard,
Mr. Kosinski.
I'm the first officer,
Commander William Riker
and this is...
Where is the
Captain, please?
He's engaged in
other duties, sir.
A ship's engines
should be the concern
of a ship's Captain.
RIKER:
They are, sir
which is why they have
made the first officer
directly responsible
for an engine's
conditions and
performance--
guided, of course,
by one of our
chief engineers
Lieutenant Commander Argyle,
in this case.
A pleasure
to meet you, sir.
I appreciated
receiving the specs.
To which you have
no end of questions.
Aye, I have.
And you, sir,
are listed as...?
As Mr. Kosinski's
assistant.
My actual name is
unpronounceable by humans.
You're from Tau Alpha C.
That's very distant.
All approved
and described
in the Starfleet
communications.
Now, I would like to
set up in the engine
room immediately.
I'll have our chief
engineer show you
to his engine room.
No need.
I know my way
around starships.
One thing that Kosinski isn't
hiding is bad disposition.
Agreed.
Also he's arrogant,
overbearing, self-important
and very sure of himself
and his ability.
And the other one?
His assistant?
He's the puzzle.
With most life-forms,
I can usually
feel something.
I may not be able
to understand or
interpret it
but I feel something,
if only a presence.
With him, nothing.
Empty space.
It's as though
he isn't even here.
Something about
this concerns me.
I don't know what.
I can point to
no reason... yet.
Stay concerned, please.
The safety
of the Enterprise
may be entrusted
to these two.
PICARD: Space,
the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out
new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
Inform the Bridge
I shall begin
my first test
in precisely
15 minutes.
Why is this
child here?
He's working on
a school project.
And before you begin
there are
some questions.
First, tell us
how you arrived...
In order to
save myself time
let me ask those
questions for you.
You received the information
which Starfleet provided
you fed it
into your computer
as precisely as
humanly possible
then you did
a controlled test
and then, to your astonishment,
nothing happened.
So you said, "What's going on?
"This doesn't work.
Kosinski's a fraud."
You see, I have had
this conversation
on other Starfleet
vessels before.
They didn't understand
it, why should you?
Surely you're not saying
it's unexplainable.
I'm saying I'm
not a teacher
nor do I wish
to become one.
I have neither the
inclination nor the time.
You have all the time
you need.
I don't think
you understand.
This has already been approved
by Starfleet Command.
But it hasn't
been approved
by the chief engineer
or by me.
( scoffs )
I didn't know
that was necessary.
Now you do.
Perhaps I should speak
to Captain Picard.
If you like.
It won't change
anything.
How basic shall I be?
I'll leave that to you.
Would you get
on the auxiliary
panel, please?
In order
to save time
my assistant is
going to lay in
my base formulas
more rapidly than
any human being
possibly could--
even myself.
So, here, then
in the simplest possible terms,
is what I do.
Now, this warp drive system
has been tuned
only in
the grossest possible sense
at least according
to my standards.
What I do is specific.
Thank you.
( indistinct chatter )
KOSINSKI:
Well, sufficient to say,
for now, that these symbols...
Something troubles you
in the way this is configured?
How about it now?
Yes.
But shouldn't
these be connected...
here...
and here?
Now will it do what
Kosinski says it will?
It has a chance.
It might work
better this way.
( whirring )
Yes.
KOSINSKI:
...as nature itself.
View with me,
if you will this screen
as we consider the following.
Now, is this merely
mechanics
or is it nature
that we deal with
in all of this?
And what else than nature
are the elementals
of space and time?
You are trained in the system.
You are... you go
in a straight line--
competent, yes,
perhaps even innovative
in a minimalist
sort of way--
but what I do here
is not the end of the process.
It is the beginning.
So what do I do?
Go back to the Fearless
which I left
with a more efficient
warp drive system
than I found?
Or do you cast off
your ignorance
and allow me to continue?
Can anything
he's proposing
damage our system?
How could it?
It's meaningless.
Then we should
let him try it?
What do you mean,
"Let him try it"?!
Don't talk about me
in the third person
as if I'm not standing
right here.
Yes, we might as well
let him try it.
Oh, yes, "We might
as well let him try it."
You are too generous.
Boy! Boy!
Don't play with that.
Captain, main Engineering
is ready to proceed.
Engineering,
this is the Bridge.
It's your call.
Do this one just like last time.
Nothing changes.
Commander,
I'll make
my preliminary
adjustments
at warp 1.5
and complete them
as we achieve
warp four.
Engineering to Bridge.
Did you copy that?
Affirmative, Number One.
You ready?
We are.
PICARD:
La Forge, set in warp 1.5.
Warp 1.5, Sir.
Engage.
All right.
Here we go.
What are you doing?
( alarms ringing )
( alarms continue )
Captain,
we're passing warp ten.
( rumbling )
What is our velocity?
It's off the scale, sir.
Reverse engines.
Captain, no one
has ever reversed engines
at this velocity.
That's because no one
has gone this fast.
Reverse engines.
All stop.
Reading all stop, sir.
Position?
Calculating it, sir.
Data, what do you read
over there?
A malfunction, I trust.
Position, Mr. La Forge.
Well, sir, according
to these calculations
we've not only left
our own galaxy
but passed through two others
ending up on the far
side of Triangulum--
the galaxy known as M-33.
That's not possible.
Data, what distance
have we traveled?
Two million, 700,000
light-years, sir.
I can't accept that.
You must, sir.
Our comparisons show it
to be completely accurate.
LA FORGE:
And I calculate that
at maximum warp, sir
it would take over...
300 years
to get home.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41263.2:
This will be a rather unusual
log entry
assuming Starfleet
ever receives it.
As I've already informed
my crew
a phenomenal surge of power
during a warp speed experiment
has sent our starship
hurtling out of our own galaxy
and past another
taking us over two million,
700,000 light-years
in a few minutes.
Message on this has already been
transmitted to Starfleet, sir.
Which, traveling subspace,
they should receive
in 51 years,
ten months
nine weeks,
16 days...
Mister Data!
Sir?
Captain Picard, I presume.
We're still trying to determine
what happened.
The truth is, Captain,
I made a mistake--
a wonderful,
incredible mistake.
Just explain
what brought us here.
As the power grew,
I applied
the energy asymptotically.
I anticipated some tilling,
but it didn't occur.
Now, that was
my error--
using the Bessel functions at
the beginning.
What is he saying,
Number One?
To tell the truth, sir,
it sounds like nonsense to me
but... considering...
Considering...
where we are...
we must assume it isn't.
WESLEY:
Can I do something to help?
I can call my mother.
She's a doctor.
No, there's nothing
she can do.
I need to rest.
I've been away
too long.
What happened to you?
Is it part of
what happened
to the ship?
Please believe me.
I mean no harm
to this vessel
or those in it.
Is Mr. Kosinski
like he sounds?
A joke?
No, that's too cruel.
He has sensed some
small part of it.
That space and time
and thought
aren't the separate things
they appear to be?
I just thought
the formula you were using
said something
like that.
Boy, don't ever
say that again
especially not
at your age
in a world that's
not ready for such...
such dangerous
nonsense.
I've always suspected
that this rate of speed
was possible, of course
but at this level--
no, never.
We're going to need new
definitions, new parameters.
You could call it
the Kosinski Scale.
Why not?
Yes, of course,
since I'm the
one who has made
the so-called warp
barrier meaningless.
And Captain, this must be
a special thrill for you.
Thrill?
Mm-hmm, as an explorer.
In three centuries
of space travel
we've charted just
11 percent of our galaxy.
And then...
we accomplish this.
Yes, but isn't the real point
can you do it again?
Can you get us home?
Well, of course, I can.
I'll just do what I did before.
Coming, Riker?
Commander Riker will
join you soon in a moment.
Comment is invited.
Counselor?
He's convinced he's right.
I've no doubt of that.
Captain, can you allow
a man who's made one mistake
back into a position
where he may make another?
Captain, what
are our options, really?
I mean, if this guy
can't get us back, who will?
Captain,
we're here.
Why not avail ourselves
of this opportunity for study?
There is a giant
protostar here
in the process
of forming.
No other vessel has
been out this far.
Spoken like a true
Starfleet graduate.
It is tempting,
eh, Number One?
Aye, sir, it is.
But as they say, sir,
you're the Captain.
I know that If Kosinski
can get us home
Starfleet can use
his technique
to bring back
a pure science vessel.
Do even more.
Number One, tell
Kosinski to prepare
to get us out of here.
Aye, sir.
Do you realize how many
great advancements of mankind
have been tied to speed?
This is a moment in history
right here, right now.
And your names will be
forever linked with mine.
Excuse me,
Commander Riker.
I don't think
he did this.
I think...
Not now, Wes.
PICARD:
Standing by, Number One.
But, sir... when
all this happened
I was watching
his assistant...
I'm sure this is
fascinating, Wesley
and I am looking forward
to hearing all about it
but not right now.
Aye, sir.
Come on.
He's too tired.
Why don't you
do it by yourself?
Yes, why not?
Uh, No, I will help.
As you wish.
I've laid in the reciprocal
course back, Captain.
Tell the Captain
I am ready, first officer.
We're ready for you
to engage, Captain.
PICARD:
As before, begin at warp 1.5.
Warp 1.5, sir.
This isn't working.
( rumbling )
All stop.
Answering all stop, Captain.
DATA:
According to the
instruments, sir
our speed never exceeded
warp 1.5.
LA FORGE:
All stopped, sir.
Yes, but where is this place?
Where none have gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41263.3:
Instead of returning
to our own galaxy
the Enterprise has gone forward
to a place in the universe
which is uncharted
and unknown.
Our present position puts us
at over a billion light-years
from our galaxy.
Data, you have the helm.
I'll be in Engineering.
( animal snarling )
What is it?
A Klingon targ.
My pet...
...from home...
...but when I was a child.
You're telling me
it's a kitty cat?
Yes.
I suppose you could
call it that.
( meowing )
( gasping )
You darling.
What are you doing here?
( meowing )
( men yelling in distance )
Now run. This place
isn't safe at all.
( men laughing and snickering )
Oh!
Tasha, what's wrong?
You look
scared to death.
I was, I was...
This is crazy.
I was at the colony
where I grew up
being chased by a rape gang.
Are you all right?
Well, you're safe now.
( playing Mozart concerto )
Captain! Captain!
We need your help!
What's wrong?
Well, don't you see
what's following us?
( music playing )
Ensign, what
are you doing?
( music continues )
( music stops )
You look tense, Jean-Luc.
Come and have a cup of tea.
Maman?
I'll make it good and strong,
the way you like it.
Maman?
We can have
a nice, long talk.
This can't be.
You've been...
Dead?
But I'm always
with you.
You know that.
Yes, I've felt that.
But why now?
Suddenly?
You mean out here?
At what you say
is the end of the universe?
Or do you see this as
the beginning of it?
We believe it the outer rim.
Maman, do you understand
these things?
Can you tell me
where my ship is?
What is this place?
Captain, you were
reported headed for...
Just a moment, Number One!
Can I help you, sir?
No.
No, let's help all of us.
General quarters,
red alert.
( siren wailing )
What is it, Captain?
Captain, why are we
at general quarters?
I have to get
everyone's attention.
This seemed to be
the quickest way.
This is the Captain.
This is not a drill.
It seems that
in this place
the world of the
physical universe
and the world
of ideas
is somehow
intermixed.
What we think
also becomes a reality.
We must, therefore
I repeat, must
begin controlling our thoughts.
We will give you
more on this
as our understanding increases.
The Enterprise will stay
at full alert
until the crisis is over.
What did you do?
It wasn't him;
it never was.
It was his
assistant.
What are you talking about?
Kosinski wasn't the one
controlling the warp experiment.
It was me!
The equations
he punched in
were nonsense,
just as we thought.
I honestly thought
it was me.
I thought somehow...
somehow I was operating
on his level.
It was also
my fault, Captain.
I should have realized
it wasn't Kosinski.
How could you?
How could any of us?
Wesley did.
If you knew something,
why didn't you say so?
He tried, twice.
I didn't listen.
He's unconscious.
Why?
I'm not
certain yet.
He phased, sir.
What does that mean?
Parts of him disappeared
and then came back.
Nobody else was
paying attention to
him the first time.
When we saw
it this time
he seemed to
be struggling,
fighting it.
BEVERLY:
He's dying.
He mustn't.
He's the only one
who can get us back.
Realistically, that
doesn't seem possible.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
Our position is unknown
and our only chance
of returning
to the known universe
is a dying alien
who is generally humanoid
but with a physiology
sufficiently different
from our own to create
medical problems
in caring for him.
Cause?
I don't know.
My equipment doesn't
register his kind
of life signs.
I would have to guess
exhaustion, fatigue.
Is he going to be all right?
What is the boy doing here?
Mom, he's my friend.
You may want him here
before we're done, sir.
He seems to have
developed some sort of
special attachment
to the boy.
My name is Wesley,
Commander Riker.
He knows.
We all know.
Will he live?
I'm not sure.
Wake him.
I recommend we let
him come around
on his own time.
We don't have that luxury.
Wake him.
He could die,
and with him any
chance we have.
Doctor, Wes...
we all have other friends
on board this ship.
If we stay here much longer,
we may lose the ability
to distinguish between
thought and reality.
Now, regardless of the risk,
wake him now.
( hissing )
Do you recognize me?
I'm the Captain
and I need answers.
I'll do my best...
to provide.
Who are you?
Or what?
I am a traveler.
A traveler?
What is your destination?
TRAVELER:
Destination?
Yes, what place are
you trying to reach?
Ah, place, no.
There is no specific place
I wish to go.
Then what is
the purpose of your journey?
Curiosity.
PICARD:
That's not
an answer.
TRAVELER:
I have certain
abilities.
They give me a knowledge
of propulsion.
I've been trading
this for passage
on Starfleet
vessels.
RIKER:
And allowing Kosinski
to take credit
for what you did?
TRAVELER:
It seemed
the sensible way.
Until now.
Captain, I seek
only transportation
in order to see
and experience your reality.
I am no threat
to you,
your ship or your crew.
He isn't, Captain.
I know he isn't.
PICARD:
Our "reality"?
And in order to satisfy
this curiosity
you have brought my ship
and my crew
into grave risk.
I have made some mistakes.
Some mistakes?
What mistakes could
possibly explain
these incredible explosions
of velocity?
I don't know if I can put this
in terms you'll understand.
I believe that there
may be a warp speed
that can get us
beyond galaxy M-33
but there is no velocity
of any magnitude
that can possibly bring us...
wherever this is.
Is it true what our navigational
sensors are telling us?
Are we... are we
millions of light-years away
from where we were?
Yes.
But what
got us here?
Thought.
Thought?
You do understand,
don't you
that thought is the basis
of all reality?
The energy of thought--
to put it in your terms--
is very powerful.
That's not an
explanation.
I have
the ability
to act like a lens
which focuses thought.
That's just
so much nonsense.
You're asking us
to believe in magic.
Well, yes, this... this could
seem like magic to you.
PICARD:
No.
No, it actually
makes sense to me.
Only the power of
thought could explain
what has been happening,
especially out here.
Thought is the essence
of where you are now.
You do understand
the danger, don't you?
Chaos.
What we think is what happens.
It pains me I was
so careless, Captain.
My intent was only to observe,
not to cause this.
You should not be here until
your far, far distant future.
Certainly not until
you've learned control.
You are from a different time,
aren't you?
No, not exactly
from another time...
well, as you understand
the concept...
yes, perhaps that term
fits as well as any.
And you have
this ability
to travel?
Yes.
And others of your kind
have the same ability?
Oh, yes.
Then why...
in all of our history,
is there no record of you
or someone like you
ever having visited us?
What wonderful arrogance.
There is no record
because we have not
visited you before.
Why not?
Well, because...
up until now,
if you'll forgive this
you've been uninteresting.
It's only now
that your life-form
merits serious attention.
I...
I'm-I'm sorry.
What's happening?
He's unconscious again.
PICARD:
Revive him.
Whatever you need from him,
you better get it soon.
If I may suggest, sir,
our first leap
out of our galaxy was,
as he said, a mistake.
PICARD:
Unless he was distracted
by something.
RIKER:
And it weakened him
in some way resulting
in the incredible leap out here.
Theory.
Do you have any facts
that fit this?
Can you get us back?
Wait, Captain,
not so fast.
We have an opportunity here
for scientific discovery.
And we report
our observations how?
To whom?
Can you get us back?
I will try.
Number One, take him down
to main Engineering.
I'll be on
the Bridge.
No!
He's very weak.
The Captain is right--
we must hurry.
But first I request
a moment with the Captain...
alone.
Strange how he seems
to care for you.
He will forget me
in time,
which is
as it should be.
It's Wesley I wanted
to speak to you about.
The boy?
It's best you do
not repeat this
to the others--
especially not
to the mother.
Whatever happens
it is imperative that
it proceed naturally.
I must get
my ship back.
Do we have time for this?
Oh, yes.
He and a few like him
are why I travel.
You have it
in your power
to encourage him
without interfering.
Encourage him in what?
How shall I explain?
Are you familiar
with the intricacies
of what is
called here "music"?
Somewhat.
And such musical genius
as I saw in one
of your ships' libraries--
one called Mozart
who as a small child
wrote astonishing symphonies.
A genius
who made music
not only to be heard
but seen and felt
beyond the understanding,
the ability of others.
Wesley is such a person.
Not with music
but with the equally
lovely intricacies
of time, energy,
propulsion...
and the instruments
of this vessel
which allow
all that to be played.
You're right.
I must hurry now
but you're right
in something else.
He is just a boy for now.
He should be encouraged
but told
none of this.
We've got to
get back home.
Take him to
main Engineering.
Yes, sir.
I'll be on
the Bridge.
Yes, sir.
( gasping )
Put it out!
How?
Think!
Put the flame
out in your thoughts.
( gasping, groaning )
Now, get to your station
and concentrate on
your assignment.
Yes, sir.
Captain's Log:
Any time entry is meaningless.
We have no choice
but to repeat
the same warp experiment
but with one variation.
A principal part
of this warp formula
will be the thoughts
of everyone aboard
the Enterprise.
We have no idea exactly
how this works.
We understand only
that the traveler
makes use of this somehow.
It will be most important
that those aboard avoid
random thoughts that might
change the reality
of what we're attempting to do.
Do you have any
further advice, Counselor?
When you begin the attempt,
there will be stress
and it's only
natural the crew's
concentration
will shift.
Plus some genuine fear, Captain.
You can't notice
what's happening outside
without feeling some of that.
( boatswain's whistle blows )
All decks, all stations
this is the Captain speaking.
All decks, I must have
your full attention.
In a few moments,
as we attempt to warp back home
it is vital--
absolutely vital--
that you center your thoughts
on your duty
or on the welfare
of the one called the traveler.
Think of giving him
some of your strength.
Now, this is an order.
You must try to do this.
And, now...
attempt to concentrate
completely
on your duty of the moment
or on the traveler
on his well-being.
Think of him as someone
you care deeply for.
All decks, all stations--
battle stations.
( alarm sounding )
I will need Kosinski
back on the main computer.
You need me?
Yes.
Helm, set in warp 1.5,
retroactive course.
LA FORGE:
Warp 1.5
retroactive 2-6-1
mark 3-1, sir.
Bridge to Engineering,
stand by.
I feel such an abundance
of well-being on the ship.
It feels like...
...quite wonderful.
RIKER:
Engineering to Bridge,
we're ready.
On my order, Mr. Data,
Mr. La Forge.
Engage.
It's not happening.
It's not enough.
Warp 1.5, sir--
which is what
my instruments
have read all along.
And our position reads
exactly what it was
before this sleigh ride
began, sir.
Cease red alert.
Sleigh ride?
Or whatever you want
to call it, Data.
I don't have
a proper name for it.
The traveler's
gone, sir.
Gone?
He's phased...
completely out
of existence--
at least out
of our existence.
( boatswain's whistle blows )
Attention all decks.
This is to inform you
that with your support
the traveler has returned us
to our own galaxy.
However, he has now left us.
Wherever he has gone,
we wish him well.
Have the boy sent to the Bridge,
Number One.
Wesley Crusher,
report to the Bridge.
On the double.
Our next assignment
is on this heading?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Data,
Mr. La Forge
increase to warp five,
same heading.
Warp five, sir.
On that same heading, sir.
Oh, Wesley,
come on the Bridge.
Move!
Commander Riker has told me
how supportive you were
in Engineering.
Well done.
Oh, at ease.
Sit here in command.
RIKER:
Captain,
it's not allowed.
Your orders.
Oh, that's true.
Well, uh, I, uh,
can't waive them again.
Only commissioned officers.
It's quite all right, sir.
I understand.
Please don't
interrupt me, Wesley.
I'm sorry, sir.
Any commissioned rank?
Even Ensign?
That would give him
authorized access
to the Bridge.
Well, then, I'll have to
make him an acting Ensign.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41263.4:
For outstanding
performance
in the best
Starfleet tradition
Wesley Crusher is
made acting Ensign
with the duties
and privileges
of that rank
and whether that rank
becomes permanent, Mr. Crusher
depends on you.
At the earliest opportunity,
your entrance application
for Starfleet Academy
will be tendered.
Until then,
you will learn this ship--
every operation, every function.
Commander Riker, a duty
schedule for Mr. Crusher
heavy on study.
Aye, sir.
Meanwhile, you can sit here
and learn something.
Sir, should I send
for Dr. Crusher?
Why, is someone ill?
Or would you rather
tell her about this, Wes?
If you don't mind, sir
I'd like to sit here
for a while.
I'll tell her later.
♪♪