Captain's log,
stardate 41249.3.
We have orbited
the two major planets
of the Beta Renner system,
taking aboard delegates
from those two worlds.
Since achieving space flight
their major life-forms--
the Anticans and the Selay--
have become deadly enemies,
but both have also applied for
admission into our Federation.
We are to deliver
these delegates
to this sector's neutral
conference planet--
called Parliament--
in the hope their dispute
can be resolved.
I'm Captain Picard.
Welcome aboard.
We hope your journey
will be pleasant
and comfortable.
Arranging that will be my
first officer, Commander Riker.
Welcome aboard.
If you'll follow me, I will
show you the accommodations...
We can already smell
the Anticans.
They were taken
aboard first?
Only because their world
was first on this heading
to Parliament.
Will our quarters
be near the Anticans?
About 100 meters apart.
Is that all right?
No.
Unsatisfactory.
I believe we can
accommodate your wishes.
We'll rearrange
the suite assignments.
If you'll follow me.
And we must be upwind
from the Anticans.
Of course, sir.
Neither seem like very promising
Federation candidates, sir.
Even Parliament's
peacemakers
may find this case
a little difficult.
But do you understand
the basis
of all this nonsense
between them?
No, sir. I never understood
that sort of hostility
even when I studied
Earth history.
Really? Oh, yes.
Well, these life-forms
feel such passionate hatred
over matters of custom,
god concepts...
even, strangely enough,
economic systems.
Sir, my sensors
are picking up
an unusual
energy object ahead.
On screen.
Confirmed, sir.
My sensors read nothing solid,
but considerable energy
in changing patterns.
Also traveling
at warp speed, sir.
Intriguing.
I can find no match with
anything in our records, sir.
Change course to make
a close sensor pass.
We can then increase
warp speed and reach
Parliament on schedule.
Aye, sir.
So, Worf, why
the interest in this?
It's just routine maintenance
on the sensor assemblies.
Simple, Geordi.
Our captain wants
his junior officers
to learn, learn, learn.
Not just his junior ones.
Okay, you hold
this relay off-line
while I adjust
these sensor circuits.
Security to
Sensor Maintenance.
Lieutenant
La Forge here.
We're making a close sensor pass
on an unusual object, Geordi.
Any problems?
Not at all, Lieutenant.
All equipment on-line
and functioning.
Sensors ready, sir.
Life-form reading?
No life-form reading, sir.
Begin the pass.
Sir, it is changing shape.
Any readings of matter there?
Negative, sir.
Energy only.
( screaming )
Worf!
La Forge to Sick Bay.
We have a medical emergency
in Sensor Maintenance.
I repeat, this is
a medical emergency.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
What happened?
I don't know.
He got hit by some sensor
feedback, maybe.
( shouts )
You got it, Doc?
I got it.
Lieutenant Worf, can you
hear what I'm saying?
( grunts )
Let's get him up.
Okay.
Come on, big guy.
On your feet.
Here we go.
That's it.
Are you okay?
He was just monitoring
the sensor console
when he jerked as though
something hit him.
What my sensors showed was...
it was a glow...
just for a second.
I can't explain it.
Could your visor device
have malfunctioned?
I doubt it, sir.
It seemed like what I was seeing
was something real.
( growls )
Sorry to call you, sir.
Not strictly security.
It's about the
dietary requirements
of the Antican delegates.
I thought that had been
taken care of in advance, Tasha.
So did we, sir.
Their live animals
were beamed aboard.
We were going to preserve
the meat for them...
but they say we must
bring it to them alive.
Then do so.
Lieutenant Yar was...
confused.
We no longer enslave animals
for food purposes.
But we have seen
humans eat meat.
You've seen something
as fresh and tasty as meat,
but inorganically materialized
out of patterns
used by our transporters.
Sickening!
It's barbaric!
He's reading normal now.
How did you manage that?
Yes. Normal.
Are you all right?
Yes. Perfectly.
Both of us...
quite normal now.
Where-- where am I?
Don't you remember?
You were in the
sensor maintenance room.
I remember monitoring
the sensor console.
What am I doing here?
That's a story
the doctor will tell you.
Obviously, you seem to feel
it's something
we should look at
more carefully.
A mystery is
only a mystery
as long as it remains
un-investigated, sir.
Mm, I love a mystery, Data,
but this one
will have to wait
until we've delivered
the delegates
to their peace conference
on Parliament.
Time and tide,
Lieutenant La Forge.
Go to warp 8.
Warp 8, sir.
Hi, Mom.
You're back early.
Yes.
Physical sciences class.
We're studying Dr. Channing's
theory on dilithium crystals.
Tell me about it.
Really?
You never seemed that interested
in warp theory before.
Doctor Channing thinks it's
possible to force dilithium
into even more useful crystals.
If, as shown here,
matter and antimatter
could be aligned
even more efficiently...
Would that affect navigation?
This is engineering,
not helm control.
Oh, yes,
the helm's located
on the bridge.
Mom?
Is something wrong?
This is the helm.
Unless there have been
some changes I don't know about.
Dr. Crusher?
You will
wish to know
Lieutenant Worf
is much improved.
Ready to return to duty.
What was the diagnosis?
A temporary
mental aberration.
Doctor!
When such a diagnosis
concerns a bridge officer
I expect a better
explanation.
Then I will have to first
run some cross-checks
on the library computer.
Klingons are so unusual
in their reactions,
aren't they?
Use Science
Station 2, Doctor.
Intriguing, Doctor.
What does helm control have
to do with medical cross-checks?
Why am I...
Is something wrong, Doctor?
Doctor?
Are you all right?
Yes.
I'll do my work
in my office.
That's where
I should be.
Do you want someone
to accompany you?
Captain, there is
a malfunction in this station.
I cannot bring
any information up on it.
Science 2 does not
function either, sir.
Engineering to Captain Picard.
We have something wrong with
warp drive circuitry, sir.
Transporter Room 6 to Bridge.
Reporting transporter
console malfunction, sir.
Data, this ship is less than
a year out of spacedock.
What are the chances
of this occurring?
It is a virtual
impossibility, sir.
So what the hell
is going on here?
And you're telling me
that there are no explanations
for these malfunctions?
At least, sir,
all the department heads
reported the
damage repaired.
That was not my question,
Number One.
What caused
the malfunctions?
I believe it was a
rampant electronic short
that jumped from system
to system, sir.
But the only thing is, um...
Yes, Mr. Singh?
That shouldn't be possible.
The affected systems
don't generally interact
with each other.
And where
they do, well...
it wasn't an interlink
that was malfunctioning.
Have you spoken
with Chief Engineer Argyle
about this problem?
With all the engineering
staff, sir.
They're just as puzzled.
Well, I'm not satisfied.
I want an explanation
of this
by the time
we reach Parliament.
But, sir...
By the time we reach
Parliament, Mr. Singh.
These weapons were taken
from two of your people
who were loitering
out of sight
in the vicinity of the Selay
delegation's quarters.
Do you care
to explain, sir?
These are not weapons,
First Officer.
They are tools.
We use these to dispatch
the animals we consume.
Your food supply is not
on the same deck
as the Selay
delegation, sir.
And you have to admit
that these could kill.
I admit some of my people
are impulsive
and we all have reason
to hate the Selay.
They appear to have the same
feelings about you, sir.
Ah, the nature
of politics.
Nevertheless,
Chief Delegate,
you are on notice
that all of your weapons,
no matter what their
basic function,
are being confiscated.
Violence will not be
tolerated on the Enterprise.
Of course not.
And if any does occur,
let me assure you
it will not be
we Anticans who start it.
Thank you, sir.
But...
we will finish it.
Sir, warp power is fading.
Picard to Engineering.
What is the problem?
We've lost the warp engine
computer tie.
Warp five... four...
three... two...
State-of-the-art vessel?
Data, signal Parliament
we'll be delayed.
We will send
a new arrival time
as soon as it is determined.
Sir...
subspace radio is out.
All right, gentlemen.
Your theories on this sudden
vulnerability in our systems.
If the Enterprise were
really this fragile, sir,
she never would
have left spacedock.
Therefore, her systems' failures
are not endemic to the ship
but are the result of the
actions of an unknown adversary.
We have a saboteur aboard.
I believe I said that.
Gentlemen,
the question is who?
I can't believe it's
one of our own people.
Agreed. There must be someone
from either alien delegation.
If the Ferengi could have bought
or bribed even one of them
that's all they'd need.
Ferengi contacts
have been detected
on both Selay
and Antica, sir.
Can either of you suggest
any other suspects?
You're sounding like
a private eye, sir.
Inquiry: private eye?
A private consulting
investigator, Data--
who solves crimes.
Hmm.
Most interesting occupation.
In the world of fact,
probably not.
However in literature,
criminal detection
can be a fascinating exercise.
The immortal Sherlock Holmes
would have an interesting
view of our mystery,
I believe.
But I'm afraid we're going
to have to find
our solution without history's
greatest
consulting detective.
How about here,
Mr. Singh?
If the control network
breaks off at this point...
It bleeds warp engine
commands off into dead ends.
Excellent.
Well, I believe I can handle
it from here, Mr. Crusher.
But, sir...
You are scheduled
for classwork now. Sorry.
Yes, sir.
But I don't learn nearly
this much in school.
Well, I tend to agree.
But the captain's orders
on this are very clear.
Hi.
Solve any new
problems today?
I was starting to,
maybe.
Mr. Singh sent me
off to class.
Wes, you're only
an acting ensign.
You've got to let the
commissioned officers
do some of the work.
Mom, I've learned a lot
more than they understand.
For example--
with Channing's
dilithium crystals theory
I was telling you about...
When were you telling me
about that?
This morning.
Don't you remember?
Honestly,
I don't remember.
Engineering to Captain Picard.
Security alert.
Picard.
Lieutenant Worf, sir.
I just found Mr. Singh.
He's dead.
Captain's log,
stardate 41249.4.
I've ordered
an immediate investigation
into the death of
Assistant Chief Engineer Singh.
We continue to run
on impulse power.
He could have been
working there
restoring warp power.
Well, according to
these readings
we can go back
to warp speed now.
Those aren't the same
readings as when I left.
Singh probably repaired it
just before he was killed.
He couldn't have
repaired it, sir.
The problems were
inside the engines.
Who else could have
corrected it, Wes?
Inform the bridge
of engine status.
Engineering to Bridge.
We now have warp capacity, sir--
all power on-line.
Well done. Warp engines ready
on previous heading.
Warp factor 6.
I tolerate these questions,
Lieutenant Yar,
because I need this vessel
to get us to Parliament.
Your shipboard problems
do not concern me.
They should.
Our delays are your delays.
( growls )
The peace conference
will wait for us.
I must ask where you were
during this vessel's
Earth hours of 1800 last night
and 0700 this morning?
Eating.
Sir, we're talking
about hours here.
( laughing )
It was a large meal,
Lieutenant Yar,
and a very interesting animal.
You wanted me, Doctor?
Yes, concerning
your memory blackout.
I still don't remember
having one.
The same thing happened to me.
I want to try hypnosis
on both of you.
It may restore your memory
as to what happened.
One thing is clear-- almost
all of the peace delegates
answered our questions
with lies.
Imprecise, Lieutenant.
They omitted certain truths
which in itself
tells us something.
We can learn something
from nondisclosure?
Indubitably, my good woman.
It's something
the captain mentioned.
Sherlock Holmes.
Indubitably...
Data has been
studying him.
Has studied, sir, every case.
As Holmes would have
pointed out,
during the time in question,
something was afoot.
Afoot?
While both sets of delegates
say they were
in their quarters,
our crew locator sensed them
passing here and here.
But since it doesn't show
where they went,
we're still in the dark.
On the contrary,
my dear colleague.
On their return,
they drew medical supplies
appropriate to the treatment
of minor wounds and abrasions
on these
life-forms.
Which leaves us
with only one conclusion.
Exactly.
That they were too engaged
in their own affairs
to have disabled the ship
and murdered the engineer.
Given the choice, they would
rather kill each other
than any of us.
It's elementary,
my dear Riker.
Sir.
Beverly, can you hear me?
Yes.
I want you to go back
in your mind
to the moment
when you first recall
this sensation
of memory loss.
Picture it exactly
as it occurred.
He's lying on
the hospital bed, sedated.
I'm walking up to him...
I...
How do you feel at this moment
as you lean over him
to take the specimen?
I feel...
someone else...
There's someone else
who's there.
Not a... not alone.
Get out.
Get out of my mind.
That's almost
exactly what you said.
As though there were
something else inside you.
Which confirms the feeling
of duality that I sensed
earlier in both of them.
Why didn't you report it?
Because, sir,
I assumed at first
it was the kind of duality that
we Betazeds feel in all of you.
Even you, sir.
When you approach
a decision
and ask yourself
which direction to go,
who are you
talking to?
Hmm.
Your hypnotism revealed
another form of duality?
Yes, sir.
I believe something
invaded them.
It's the only
possible conclusion.
Data...
Let's proceed
without the pipe.
Yes, sir, if you wish, sir.
But I ask if you take it
as incontrovertible
that it cannot be
a family member
or one of the crew?
Yes, very unlikely.
Then our investigation
was worthwhile, sir.
We've eliminated
both the delegates
and the ship's
regular complement.
Data, what are you suggesting?
I am referring to the great
detective's credo, sir.
I quote--
"We must fall back
on the old axiom
"that when other
contingencies fail,
"whatever remains
however improbable
must be the truth."
( water gurgles )
That engine computer net
wasn't repaired, sir.
It just suddenly
became all right.
Sometimes, it's the result
that counts, you know?
What the... oh, no.
What is it?
Helm control just went down.
She won't respond.
Bridge to Captain.
You're needed here immediately.
Wes, alert engineering from
your panel, all right?
I'm trying.
Report.
Helm is down, sir.
There's no apparent reason.
Captain, we've just dropped
to impulse power.
Sir, are you all right?
I thought I just saw...
I'm fine.
Everything is fine now.
Why the drop to impulse power,
Lieutenant?
The helm is suddenly
malfunctioning, sir.
Malfunctioning?
You're wrong. Look again.
Captain, I was just...
Mr. La Forge?
Well, there's nothing
wrong with it now, sir.
Everything is
just as it should be.
In that case,
make our heading
925 mark 3... 7.
Sir?
You have a problem
with that heading, Lieutenant?
You want to double back
on our course, sir?
Isn't that what I ordered?
GEORDI:
Yes, sir.
Sir... I'm puzzled by
your reversing our course.
That energy cloud, Commander.
I believe it important
we have another look at it.
But we're behind schedule
for Parliament already.
I believe a very important
scientific discovery
awaits us on this heading.
Perhaps you'd like to share
your reasoning on that, sir?
Yes, since we obtained
only minimal information
on our sensor pass of it.
Right, Data.
We must go back to learn more.
Counselor...
do you believe
a ship captain
should explain every order?
Of course not, sir.
I demand to see
the captain!
Stop! Return
to your quarters!
( shriek of disgust )
What is that doing
on our deck?
I demand to know why this
starship has changed its course!
Please return
to your quarters, delegates.
( hostile growls )
A mere change of direction
hardly justifies mutiny.
Exactly what do you believe
you're sensing from him?
It's just the
feeling that...
well, that he's closed
part of his mind to me.
I just feel
that the captain
has become...
perhaps dangerous.
If he's dangerous...
if...
Then he'd have to be
relieved of command.
Which you could do, Doctor.
It's beaucoup trouble
if you're wrong.
And at the moment,
it is all pure speculation.
He's done nothing to subject
the Enterprise to danger.
I'd need a medical log citing
clear evidence of incapacity.
You could do it
without that problem.
Only if all command officers
agreed it was vital to do so.
But he has not been showing
any overt unusual behavior.
Ultimately,
I believe he will.
As second in command,
it's still in your corner.
I'll order medical
and psychiatric exams.
You'll have to back
me up somehow.
First officer's log,
supplemental.
After meeting
with the senior officers,
Dr. Crusher and I have decided
to approach the captain
regarding his recent behavior.
( door shuts )
Yes?
I'd like you to come
to Sick Bay
for some examinations,
Captain.
Oh?
I'd be glad to,
when I'm free.
I'd like to conduct
them now, sir.
Why?
What can I do for you,
Number One?
Sir, counselor Troi has
recommended the examinations.
Same question-- why?
It is my duty to
inform the captain
we believe he may be under
some kind of alien influence
which may constitute
a danger to this ship.
I consider it
equally possible
that the two of you,
and counselor Troi,
are overworked
and possibly suffering
hallucinations.
Now, this is an order--
you will arrange medical
and psychiatric exams
both for yourself
and them.
Doctor, are you aware everyone
is behaving strangely?
I'm concerned that
you've suddenly turned
the ship away
from its course...
What's happened
to your mind, Doctor?
The search for knowledge is
always our primary mission.
I'm sorry. I...
I really am too busy
for this kind of nonsense.
Do I have to call security
to force you to report
to the Sick Bay?
No, sir.
What the hell?!
Sorry, wrong species.
Riker to security chief!
Yar here.
Security guard
to the engineering deck.
The Selays are playing
hide-and-seek down here,
obviously with the Anticans.
It's a lethal game.
I want them returned
to quarters, under guard!
Right away, sir.
( chime sounds )
Come.
What do you want?
Here are the results from the
exams you ordered, sir.
You don't care
to inspect them?
Please...
are you Jean-Luc?
He is here.
The Jean-Luc I know?
And more.
The more frightens me.
And elates us.
We wish you could understand
the glorious adventure ahead.
You and...
Soon we'll both be home.
First officer's log,
supplemental.
On the orders
of Captain Picard,
we have returned
to the vicinity
of the energy pattern cloud.
I am personally convinced
that something from this cloud
now shares the captain's mind.
But there seems to be
nothing we can do--
at least within regulations.
We're now approaching
the cloud, sir.
Very well, Mr. La Forge.
Bring us to within 10,000
kilometers and hold us there.
Aye, sir.
Shall we begin the scientific
tests you wanted, sir?
Oh, they're already underway.
I have an announcement
for the entire bridge.
As many of you suspected,
when our ship passed
through the edge of this,
it accidentally carried away
a sentient being--
much like these
energy patterns
we're seeing here.
A terrifying experience
for any intelligent being--
as if a great claw reached
down and scooped one of you
from your home world.
Drawn in to the energy
circuits of this vessel.
It found its way
to you, Worf.
Frantic at being taken
from its home world
and recognizing you
as sentient beings,
it pleaded for help,
but in ways
you couldn't understand.
Desperately going
from person to person.
And then discovering
the computer intelligence
in this ship's
memory circuits.
Oh, simplistic intelligence--
but it furnished it enough
to slow this Enterprise thing
that had captured it.
And it very much regrets
the accidental death
of engineer Singh.
Captain...
do you exist
in combination
with this entity?
Is it in control
of you, sir?
Very soon after
we had combined
we had learned much
about each other.
Passion for exploration,
for the unknown--
we found we had
similar dreams.
And it offered your
captain a way
to realize them
beyond human
expectations.
RIKER:
Captain!
I must speak to you
privately, now!
I understand.
As an energy pattern,
free of the limitations
of matter,
he might travel anywhere.
At any velocity.
Captain, do you hear me?
Sir, I see no way for you to
journey with an energy form.
Isn't there?
He's planning to beam himself
and the entity
into that cloud.
The transporter need not pattern
your captain into matter.
We'll beam energy only
and we will become
a combined energy pattern
of our life-forms.
A resignation from this command
and from Starfleet has been
appropriately
recorded.
I refuse to allow this, sir.
How does this resignation
threaten the ship
or its crew in any way?
Captain Picard, you are
now relieved of duty.
I judge you
to be disabled
and mentally
incapacitated.
RIKER:
Security!
Red alert!
( alarm sounding )
Restrain the captain!
Where is he?
This is
blinding me!
WORF:
Captain!
I'll help you
if you let me!
Someone restrain the captain!
( alarm continuing )
RIKER:
First officer's log,
supplemental.
More than an hour has passed
since the captain beamed out,
energy only.
Every effort has been made
to determine his whereabouts.
The transporter
chief has no idea
what the coordinates
were, sir.
So he's just floating
around out there?
How can we
settle for that?
Give me a choice, then.
Still no readings,
no sign of anything.
Mr. La Forge...
it's time to set a course
for Parliament.
Warp 8.
We're really leaving him?
Commander... wait!
It's the captain.
But only the captain.
He's out there alone.
The entity,
has it abandoned him?
No.
But the combination wasn't
possible out there.
He's in trouble,
so we have to beam him back.
Beam him back as what?
He's nothing but energy now.
Sir, the entity was caught
in the ship's circuitry.
The captain might try
to get in the same way
if he's in trouble.
Bring us in closer, La Forge.
Moving in, sir, but where?
There's no way to know.
Let's hope he can come
part way himself.
Troi, is there any way
you can get a message to him?
I wish I could.
Sensors monitoring
the perimeter...
ship's circuitry, sir--
nothing.
Bring us right into the edge
of it, La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Sir!
On my sensor controls.
There's something here.
I feel it.
Just as before,
going to Worf first.
Something crazy on my panel.
Commander Riker...
GEORDI:
Static?
"P" for Picard?
He's in the ship's
circuitry.
Come to the transporter
room, please.
There might be
a way, sir. Hurry!
This is a wild theory, Data.
I knew we had to have
the captain's physical
pattern here, sir.
He was the last one
to beam out.
Is what you're
thinking possible?
Unknown at this time, sir.
I hope the captain remembers
his physical pattern is here.
If he has,
his energy has moved
into the transporter
relays by now.
I wish we had some sign
that he was in here.
I guess we have no choice
but to risk it.
Energizing, sir.
What the devil am I doing here?
Sounds like our captain.
But confused.
This Picard pattern was formed
before he went
out there.
What's happening to me,
Number One?
I was preparing to...
to beam out...
to somewhere.
And I remember there
was talk of an entity.
But it all seems so vague.
I believe the captain is now
his separate self, sir.
Much of what happened
is naturally missing.
What are you talking
about, Data?
Is this still
Sherlock Holmes?
Indubitably, sir.
Indubitably.
Hmm. At least you got rid
of that damned pipe.
Dr. Crusher has asked me
to steer you past Sick Bay.
She said you've been
looking very tired.
Captain!
Yes, Lieutenant.
Sorry, Commander,
but Security Team Two reports
they've discovered a puddle of
blood outside the Selay quarters
and they can't find
one of the delegates...
Lieutenant, this couldn't
have waited a moment?
It's good to see you, sir.
The problem is is that one of
the cooks has just been asked
to broil reptile
for the Anticans
and it looks like
the Selay delegate.
Riker, what with the
peace delegates and all,
I think I do
need a rest.
Take charge,
Number One.