Captain's Log,
Stardate 41255.6:
After delivering a party
of Earth colonists
to the Strnad solar system,
we have discovered
another class M planet
in the adjoining
Rubicun star system.
We are now in orbit there
having determined it
to be inhabited
as well as unusually lovely.
My first officer has taken an
away team down to make contact
and they are in the process
of returning to the ship.
Riker says
the planet's life-forms
are almost identical to us.
He's very enthusiastic.
Captain...
sorry, Troi.
The Doctor has something very
important to tell you, Captain.
You've been talking
about it for days--
shore leave for the crew.
Establishing this colony
has been exhausting
for the entire
crew, Captain.
We're not a supply vessel.
Settling all those people
has been a strain on everyone.
I'm tired myself.
Is it as good as your
report suggests, Number One?
As per report, sir.
Class M--
earthlike, beautiful.
It will startle you.
Sounds wonderful
for the children.
The holodecks are
marvelous, of course,
but there's nothing
like open spaces
and fresh air.
I've listed my report on
their customs and laws, sir.
Fairly simple--
common sense things.
LA FORGE:
They're wild in some ways
actually puritanical
in others.
Neat as pins, ultra-lawful.
They make love
at the drop of a hat.
Any hat.
But the happiest report
has its negatives.
Let's start with them,
Number One.
There are none, sir--
none that any of us could find.
But there is
a problem here, sir.
It's the faulty reading
I reported, sir.
I'm reading something
off the starboard bow
but there is
nothing there.
Sensor technicians
are working on it, sir.
They have identified it
as a glitch in the system.
I take it you find no glitch
at all in this planet, however.
No, sir.
If you approve
shore leave, sir,
we could start
with a small group.
Of course.
Wesley, if we go down,
I'd like you
to join the away team
to evaluate this planet
as a place for young
people to relax.
Yes, sir.
If our scans and observations
confirm the report,
of course I'll approve it.
Let's just hope it's not
too good to be true.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Supplemental:
We are in orbit of a planet
designated Rubicun 3
the home of a life-form
who call themselves the Edo.
Our away team,
including Wesley Crusher,
has beamed down to
make some arrangements
concerning some
well-earned recreation.
Careful, sir.
No, it's all right, Lieutenant.
Those are the Edo
we met before.
They certainly are fit.
They certainly are.
Health and happiness!
A pleasant day to you!
You did return as promised.
Rivan, Liator.
Also from our vessel,
Troi and...
Slowly, slowly.
I must welcome
this lovely one.
Nice to see you again.
My pleasure.
RIKER:
Counselor?
Healthy sensuality, sir.
I feel mainly friendship
and, um...
happiness.
And I welcome this huge one.
Oh, yes!
Nice planet.
Yeah.
But you are a young one.
I do not know your custom
regarding love.
Uh...
I guess...
whatever you usually do.
There are others
who would like to visit here
if you would give us
a limit on the number.
Whatever pleases you.
We'll discuss it
at the council chambers.
Shall we go there now
or remain and play?
Play?
At love.
Unless you don't enjoy that.
Perhaps you do.
And you.
Yes, I can see that you do.
Maybe I should just
go on ahead.
Oh, this is unfair to him.
We'll go on to
the council chambers.
You'll find young people
your age there.
Well, I can't
make any promises.
You don't have to.
Our rules are simple.
No one does anything
uncomfortable to them.
Come, our people will
want to know you.
Rivan, perhaps
they can't run.
Can't run?
Of course we can run.
Right, Commander?
That's the custom here--
running.
Lead the way.
When in Rome, eh?
When in where, sir?
Good health to you!
Happiness to you!
It's like an Eden here.
Good health!
I thought you might be
out of breath.
We may surprise you
in a lot of ways.
Children, we've brought
you a new friend.
Well, hello!
Join us.
Yes, please.
Come on!
This way.
And now it's time for you
to meet some new friends.
Everyone!
We've brought
the visitors.
Please, enjoy what we have.
Come with me.
I've traced it through
our sensor channels, sir.
It's not a glitch or any other
form of error or malfunction.
That's confirmed
by my readings, Captain.
It's a shadow something.
Exactly, as if it were neither
in or out of our dimension.
What is, Commander?
Whatever is sitting
out there
without triggering
our alarm relays, sir.
Center main viewer
on that area.
I see nothing, Commander.
Enterprise to object
off our starboard bow.
Request that you
identify yourself.
( alarm blaring )
Shields and deflectors
up full, sir.
Main phaser banks ready.
Hailing frequencies--
any reply?
It was something
unintelligible, sir.
Now running it through
language and logic circuits.
Geordi?
Sir?
Have a real look.
Aye, sir.
Sir, my sensors read it...
well, as half there.
And it does look as if
it were partly transparent.
Data, what the hell is it?
Lieutenant La Forge
to Captain.
Go ahead, La Forge.
What can you make out?
This is something
I've never seen before, sir.
After complete spectral
analysis, it's...
well, it's as if
it's not really there.
I don't understand it.
I've got some information
on its first transmission, sir.
It translates as "stand by."
Sir, I see something
coming out of that ship.
Verified, sir.
Something very small.
What is it?
Intruder alert, sir.
I don't show
a location.
The away team signal
has been cut off, Captain.
We've lost contact
with our people.
Intruder relays
do show something.
Why has everything become
a "something" or a "whatever"?
MALE VOICE:
State... the... purpose.
State the purpose
of what you have done.
I'm Captain Picard
commanding this
Federation starship.
State the purpose
of your visit here.
We have sent down
what we call an away team
to make peaceful contact here.
Do you plan to leave
life-forms here?
No.
We are merely visiting here.
But you did more at the world
you just left.
Why have you left
your own life-forms there?
The colony we
just planted, sir.
We found that world
uninhabited.
The life-forms
we left there had...
had sought the challenge--
at least, that is
the basic reason--
had sought the challenge
of creating a new lifestyle--
a new society there.
Life on our world
is driven
to protect itself
by seeding itself
as widely as possible.
Do not interfere
with my children below.
Captain...
I do not
understand how
but it is asking me
if I was constructed
for information exchange.
If there is any way
of finding out
whatever it is
out there, Data...
Watch! I bet you
can't do this!
Watch this.
I want to do something,
too, with you.
Uh, what?
It's something you can
teach me. Will you?
Uh... well, actually,
there are some games
I don't quite know yet.
It's playing ball.
Will you teach me?
Oh, sure.
If you have a bat
for the ball,
I can show you
my favorite.
A bat?
A stick or a branch.
Um, about this long,
this thick.
We can get it in the gardens.
Come on!
This will please you.
Join us.
Thanks, another time.
Joy and happiness.
It certainly is.
The good life, Worf.
I am not concerned
with pleasure, Commander.
I am a warrior.
Even Klingons need
love now and then.
For what we consider love, sir,
I would need a Klingon woman.
What about plain old basic sex?
You must have
some need for that.
Of course, but with the females
available to me, sir--
Earth females--
I must restrain myself
too much.
They are quite fragile, sir.
Worf, if anyone else
had said that,
I'd suspect
he was bragging.
Bragging, sir?
I think I'll
pass on that.
I better check in.
Enterprise, come in.
Captain, do you read me?
Let's...
This may be nothing,
but let's move
all our people together.
Including Wesley, the boy?
He's outside.
Is there a problem?
We've lost contact
with our ship.
Well, it's nothing
these people have done.
I'm certain of that.
Their minds are so open.
Help me locate Wes.
He's wandered off.
That is extraordinary.
May I take a moment of
your time, Lieutenant?
Yes, Worf, but you've got
to hear this.
Are you telling me that there's
no crime here whatsoever?
No one breaks
any laws?
Once they did.
Long, long ago,
there was much disorder.
But not now.
But I've seen no sign
of police.
Those who enforce laws.
RIVAN:
Oh, we have very few.
They are called mediators
and they are needed only
in one place each day.
The punishment zone,
an area that's selected
for a period of time.
It's a completely
random selection?
No one but our mediators
know what place
or for how long.
We're very proud of
the wisdom of our ancestors.
No person ever knows where
or when a zone will be.
And so no one
risks death.
Death?
By breaking any law.
Wait, explain this.
Only one punishment
for any crime.
Anyone who commits any crime
in the punishment zone dies?
The law is the law.
Our peace is built on that.
Even a small thing...
such as ignoring the rule
"keep off the grass"?
Well, then,
no one breaks that rule.
Who wants to risk execution?
And there's always
a white wall or fence
to remind anyone
of a forbidden area like that.
And just who tells visitors
about these rules?
We'd better find Wesley.
( laughing )
Here.
Catch, catch.
All right. Over here.
Yeah!
Throw it back.
All right. Oh, good catch.
Here it comes.
Right here.
There you go.
Hey!
Here it comes.
You're very
clever at this.
At home, we play a lot of it.
Here, toss the ball
ahead of me.
No, Wes!
No, it's forbidden
to disturb new plants.
Couldn't you
see the fence?
It's for new plants.
Don't ever past
a white marker.
It's okay.
I'm fine.
Oh, no!
Oh, please, no!
Speak the truth.
We are mediators.
I said I was fine.
He doesn't know!
He's from another place!
How very sad, but this zone
has been selected.
But he doesn't understand.
It's always sad.
Now doubly so.
I was chasing
a ball
and I fell into that.
I'm really sorry.
You admit you
did that?
Freely?
I'm with Starfleet.
We don't lie.
It won't happen again.
We apologize.
We're sorry, too,
but that
changes nothing.
Careful, Commander.
They've got some
strange laws here.
I thought you
reviewed their laws.
But they listed nothing
about punishment.
One moment, please.
Is there a witness
to this transgression?
But it was my fault.
I threw
the ball past him.
We have a visible
transgression
ample witnesses
and an admission
of guilt.
And though it pains
us deeply to do it, we must.
Are you prepared
for punishment?
Punishment?
If you mean what the others
were talking about...
What punishment? Name it.
Death, of course.
Don't make it
difficult for the boy.
Drop it!
Drop it now!
It's a kind of syringe.
What is this?
You said death.
Is this poison?
But... but of course it is--
completely painless.
The boy would have
felt nothing.
But look at him now.
You frightened him.
He was going to kill me?
And if this zone
was still in effect,
you would all deserve death.
It was announced
you came as friends.
Is this how
friends act?
Enterprise from away team.
Come in.
Are you receiving us,
Enterprise?
Condition?
No sign of
consciousness
but the balance
of the readings
are quite normal
for him.
I believe this is some form
of information exchange
with whatever is over there.
At least, I hope it is.
Any communication
from the away team?
Something is blocking
communication both...
YAR:
Security, urgent.
Repeating,
Enterprise from away team.
This is the Enterprise,
Lieutenant.
We're receiving you now.
This is an urgent call
for Captain Picard.
RIKER:
We may need your presence
here, Captain.
We have serious trouble
with a member of our away team
and an unusual law
they have here.
Captain to Riker. Stand by.
Any signs of consciousness?
Not yet.
It could be
minutes or hours.
It's unclear what's
happened to him.
Take him to Sick Bay, let me
know the instant he's awake.
Anything new on
that thing over there?
Negative, sir.
Captain to First Officer,
I'm beaming down.
Would you care to
comment privately
on how you read
any of this?
Unnecessary, sir.
These people are honest,
almost to a fault,
and they have great pride
in their ways.
You're the Captain?
We're ready.
This way, please.
Welcome to our world, Captain.
Thank you.
We regret that our system of
justice is troubling you.
The boy, Wesley Crusher,
where is he, please?
In accord
with the Prime Directive,
I've allowed them to hold him
pending the outcome of this.
He is safe
and unharmed.
We promise that.
Captain Picard, I do not
know how you Earth people
conduct law and justice--
even if you respect
such things.
We do.
Good. So do we.
Our precepts have been
handed down from long ago.
The tranquility you see in
our lives has been made possible
by our laws.
RIVAN:
We are a people of law.
They do sometimes
bring us sadness,
but we have learned
to adjust to that.
Perhaps your laws
work as well?
They haven't always,
but now they do.
Do you execute criminals?
No, not any longer.
RIVAN:
But you did once?
Unfortunately, yes.
But since then...
And when you did, was it
believed necessary to do so?
Some people felt
that it was necessary,
but we have learned to detect
the seeds of criminal behavior.
Capital punishment,
in our world,
is no longer considered
a justifiable deterrent.
So...
we are not yet
as advanced as they are.
And since you are advanced
in other ways, too,
I suggest you use your superior
powers to rescue the Wesley boy.
We will record him
as a convicted criminal
out of our reach--
an advanced person who luckily
escaped the barbarism
of this backward little world.
Unfortunately, we have a law
known as the Prime Directive.
Riker has explained it to us.
Is the boy in any danger
from you at this moment?
Until sundown?
Because you
are strangers,
we are delaying
enforcement of the law,
but we must act
by sundown.
Then I have another question.
While orbiting-- while circling
high above your world--
as we do, we have
encountered a strange object.
A vessel, perhaps.
Have you any idea what it is?
It's not entirely real.
At least it's not
completely solid.
Do you mean God?
God?
God is said to be
somewhere up there
protecting us.
Exactly...
exactly how would you
describe God?
As you just did.
As existing both here
and in another place, also.
But when God wants to
show its power,
it can make itself felt
most fully.
BEVERLY:
Captain, come in, please.
Picard here.
CMO Crusher, sir.
Commander Data has just
regained consciousness.
What condition? Can he talk?
He's insisting on it,
sir, urgently.
Wesley...
Stand by. Picard out.
I want to speak to her
personally about her son.
And so you promise that Wesley
Crusher is safe until sundown?
You have our word.
Then will one of you
return with me to our ship?
Of course.
I'll go as a hostage
for the boy's safety.
No, no, no, that's not it.
I want you to identify
something for me, if you can.
Picard to Transporter Room,
three to beam up.
I'm frightened.
There's no
reason to be.
Transporter Room,
energize.
But this is a city!
A great city.
Captain, I've just seen the
away team report about Wesley.
In a moment, Doctor.
In a moment?!
Exactly. In a moment.
You were about to say?
Well, since you have
all this power,
why be concerned
about our laws?
You could take
the boy from us.
It's not that simple.
From the
starboard lounge
you can see whatever
is outside this vessel.
Do you mean my world?
You said we'd be
high above it.
And something else
that's circling your world.
It's very
important to us
and perhaps to you
to know what it is.
I'm sorry, Rivan,
but this was necessary.
Do you know what that is?
Can you tell us
what it is?
Is it God?
Now, it's very important
that you answer something.
How do you recognize
what it is?
Nothing will harm you,
I promise.
Just tell us
how you recognize it.
It has appeared before.
Can you speak to it?
Does it speak
to you?
Captain!
Return my child!
Return?
It's coming
towards us.
Picard to Transporter Room.
Come in.
Yes, do that, but hurry!
It's still coming towards us.
Transporter Chief to Captain.
One to beam down
to away team location.
Hurry!
Engage, Transporter
Room. Urgent, engage!
It seems the Edos' god is
very protective of its children.
I had no choice but to learn
about that thing from her.
I'm sorry I had to.
She was so frightened.
It's understandable, sir.
Sharing an orbit with God
is no small experience.
Let's go see your patient,
Doctor.
What do you intend
to do about my son?
He's being held safely
until sundown.
When he faces execution!
Although he's
committed no crime--
certainly none any sane
and reasonable person...
You saw what that thing
was about to do.
I apologize, sir,
but this is very
difficult for me.
If he were your son,
you'd be as frightened...
But I am.
Data's in Sick Bay here.
You'll find him able
to talk to you.
He's checking out
fine, Doctor.
Thank you.
Finish it later, please.
I was an excellent choice
for them, Captain.
They were able to
communicate with me quite...
I was about to say
quite easily,
but there was nothing
easy about it.
Fortunately,
they stopped short
of overloading
my circuitry.
You're saying they?
So it is a vessel of some sort?
Definitely not a single entity,
if that's what you mean, sir.
Although they know the Edo
worship them as a god thing.
They know?
They recognize that this is
quite expected and harmless
at the present Edo stage
of evolution.
What sort of vessel?
It is perhaps not
what we would understand
as a vessel, sir.
The dimensions this one occupies
allows them to be...
well, to be
in several places at once.
That they consider that this
entire star cluster is theirs.
It was probably unwise of us
to attempt to place
a human colony in this area.
Of course, there are
3,004 other planets
in this star cluster in which
we could have colonized.
The largest and closest...
Data! Don't babble.
Babble, sir?
I am not aware
that I ever babble, sir.
It may be
that from time to time
I have considerable
information to communicate
and you may question the way
in which I organize it...
Please, organize it into
brief answers to my questions.
We have very little time.
Do they accept
our presence at this planet?
Undecided, sir.
Data, please feel free
to volunteer
any important information.
I volunteer
that they are now
observing us, sir.
To judge what kind
of life-forms we are?
No. It is more curiosity.
I doubt that they expect us
to abide by their value systems.
Do they know
of our Prime Directive?
They know everything I know,
sir.
And if we were to violate
the Prime Directive...
That's not a fair question.
How would they react?
That would be a case of judging
us by our own rules, sir.
If we violate
our own Prime Directive,
they might consider us to be
deceitful and untrustworthy.
You do recall,
they cautioned us
not to interfere with
their children below.
What has happened?
The Edo want to
execute my son.
I will not allow that
to happen, Jean-Luc!
Most interesting, sir.
The emotion
of motherhood
as compared to all others
felt by humans...
Shut up!
You were right, sir.
I do tend to babble.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41255.9:
Whatever the object
or vessel in orbit with us,
it hangs there
like a nemesis.
It is one thing to communicate
with something mysterious,
but it is quite another
to be silently observed by it.
I am concerned
whether it understands
the same concept
of reason that we do.
You sent for me, sir?
Let's have
more talk, Data.
Yes, sir.
Sit down.
What level of
communication, sir?
Any.
My apologies for saying
that you babbled.
But I do, sir.
You also see things
in a way we do not
but as they truly are.
I need help, my friend.
I cannot permit that boy
or any member of this vessel
to be sacrificed.
The Prime Directive
never intended that.
The problem, sir, is there.
Although they have learned
of the Prime Directive
from my mind,
how will they evaluate it?
How do they reason?
What are their values?
Remember their
warning to us, sir.
Exactly.
How do I explain my refusing
to obey their laws down there?
Not permitting
the Crusher boy...
to be executed.
And by so doing,
do I endanger this vessel
and more than
a thousand other lives?
Would you choose one life
over 1,000, sir?
I refuse to let arithmetic
decide questions like that.
Did you learn anything
about the relationship
between that and the Edo?
Why are they so certain
it's a god?
Any sufficiently
advanced life-form
would appear to others
to be that, sir.
But when they were probing
my thoughts, Captain,
I could feel that
whatever they are now,
they once existed in this
dimension just as we do--
perhaps in the same kind
of flesh and blood form.
Since then, however,
they have evolved
considerably.
Their present existence
in multi-dimensions
no doubt has advantages
we do not understand.
Then, in some earlier
flesh-and-blood form,
they might have shared
our kind of values?
We know the Edo
share them, sir.
Why would such
an advanced thing
feel obliged
to protect the Edo?
Perhaps the Edo are
a child race, by comparison.
Possibly a race which...
those life-forms
have planted here
much as we now plant
human colonies
on class M planets.
Having fulfilled
my professional obligations
regarding Commander Data...
You now request permission
to beam down to the planet.
Permission granted.
You can accompany me
while I try and resolve this.
And you should know
that whatever the cost
I will not allow them
to execute your son.
Thank you, sir.
Data, take command.
Aye, sir.
It's almost time.
I want the boy
brought here now.
I'll go with you.
Of course.
Captain Picard.
I saw you share
the sky with God.
You must be gods.
No, no, we're not gods.
Mother.
I guess you know
a lot has happened here.
I know.
Captain Picard...
are you going to
let them kill me?
No.
But I must find some way to
prevent it that you understand.
How can we let
this happen, Liator?
They threaten
everything we respect.
Our law, our peace,
our tranquility and order.
You are powerful,
but do not do this to us.
We beg you.
At least, study what
we were without law--
hurtful to each other,
savage, thieving.
I understand.
Perhaps your system of law
and punishment
is better than any system
we once had,
but we do now have a law
and must obey.
And part of it says
that I must protect
my people from harm.
We did not ask you
to come here.
Which has to do
with another law
that we must obey.
We are all sworn
not to interfere
with other lives
in the galaxy.
If I save this boy,
I break that law.
And you should
be executed if you do so.
I may suffer almost as much.
Starfleet takes the Prime
Directive very seriously.
No, it is God
who will punish you.
That thought
has crossed our minds.
Your God up there may insist
that we obey our
noninterference directive.
Sir, does this mean
if you save me,
the entire crew could die?
You're not involved
in this decision, boy.
I'm sorry, sir,
but it seems like I am.
Picard to Transporter Room.
Lock in to this signal.
Stand by for six
to beam up.
Wesley, Lieutenant.
Our laws have been violated.
What of justice?
What of justice to Wesley?
Does he deserve to die?
I'm truly sorry, Liator,
but I must have justice
for my people, too.
Transporter Room, energize.
Transporter Room, come in.
We can't energize the beam, sir.
Everything checks out,
but we're getting no results.
God has prevented
your escape.
Then your God
is unfair.
My son had no warning
that his act was criminal.
We cannot allow
ignorance of the law
to become a defense.
I don't know how
to communicate this,
or even if it is possible,
but the question of justice has
concerned me greatly of late.
And I say to any creature
who may be listening,
there can be no justice
so long as laws are absolute.
Even life itself
is an exercise in exceptions.
When has justice ever been
as simple as a rule book?
Seems the Edo Lord agrees
with you, Number One.
Main viewer on.
Hailing frequencies.
Open, sir.
To the object in orbit with us.
We will remove
the human colonists
from the adjoining solar system
if you signal us
to do so.
Please tell us.
Captain.
Is that a signal?
I suppose...
I suppose it must be.
I was hoping for more.
More of what, sir?
I'm glad it's gone.
Agreed, sir,
short and sweet.
Godlike efficiency.
I was hoping we might learn
more about it,
but since we can't,
take us out of here,
Number One.
Gladly, sir.