Captain's log,
Stardate 41723.9.
In response
to a Starfleet order,
we are in the Xendi Sabu
star system
having rendezvoused
with a Ferengi vessel
which has requested a meeting.
Although we arrived here
and made appropriate signals
to the Ferengi three days ago
they have so far responded only
with the message,
"Stand by, Enterprise."
( door chime )
You sent for me, sir?
Yes, doctor.
Sit down.
Um, look...
this, perhaps,
may be nothing
but I've been feeling
a bit odd of late.
Uh, fatigued.
And now I've got
this damned headache.
A what?
Headache, headache.
Surely you know
what a headache is.
Of course.
But I don't often
encounter them.
The reason is
obvious, of course.
What are the Ferengi up to?
"Stand by, Enterprise."
Stand by for what?
I don't see a thing wrong.
No, neither can i--
unless they're baiting
some kind of trap.
With your head.
I see nothing
physically wrong.
But I want to run some
additional scans in Sick Bay.
Doctor, all I've got is...
Is an order to report
to Sick Bay
from the only
person aboard this ship
who can give you an order.
RIKER:
Captain from first officer.
They're finally
sending a message.
On my way, Number One.
Sorry, doctor.
Duty calls.
RIKER:
They're prepared
to talk, sir.
Have they given any hint of
what they've been waiting for?
Negative, captain.
They've identified their
commander as Bok.
DaiMon Bok.
You'll be able
to see him now, sir.
They're willing to communicate
on visual.
Open hailing
frequencies.
TASHA:
Frequencies open, sir.
Ferengi vessel, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
We are transmitting visually.
Is this the Captain Picard?
Do we know each other?
I know you, Picard.
Then you have
the advantage of me.
Is this Bok?
I am Bok,
DaiMon of the Ferengi.
I have asked you here
to discuss a mutual
problem, Captain.
What problem is that,
DaiMon Bok?
I insist on speaking
of that matter in person.
Shall we meet
on your vessel
or mine?
Hailing frequencies
closed.
Captain, I sense considerable
deception on Bok's part.
And danger!
Then we should
meet him here.
Keep him under
our control.
Now open, sir.
I appreciate your offer,
DaiMon Bok.
We would like you
to be our guest here?
As you wish, Picard.
Perhaps this will begin
a new era of cooperation
for both our people.
In one Earth hour, then?
In one hour, DaiMon Bok.
End transmission.
I can't believe
they're coming here.
They did agree
a bit easily.
In one hour,
we shall know why.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Are you always accustomed to
getting your own way, Doctor?
Only when my way
makes sense, Captain.
There's still 40 minutes
until the Ferengi beam over.
I'll have these scans
done in 10.
Seems an awful lot of effort
for something as simple
as a headache.
As simple?
You should
not have a headache
unless there's
something wrong, sir.
It may be true that headaches
were once quite common.
That was in the days before
the brain was charted,
before we understood
the nature of pain.
When we were suffering
from things
such as the common cold.
So what's the cause
of my headache?
I haven't the slightest idea.
Feel better?
The pain's gone.
Medical fakery.
The pain is actually
still there.
It's just cloaked.
I'll want further exams.
Doctor...
When the Ferengi matter
is settled.
Commander, you'll soon
be getting an intruder alert.
What? Wesley, if you've
something to report...
If you'll scan heading 44 mark
163, Lieutenant, you'll find...
TASHA:
Intruder alert, sir.
I've got something, sir.
It's an old-style starship, sir.
Constellation class, heading
this way under impulse power.
Says who?
Ensign, answer
the first officer's question.
Says the long-distance
sensors, sir.
I was in Engineering,
playing around
with boosting
the sensor output...
Boosting it?
How?
We will discuss this later.
I'm reading it now, sir.
It's a constellation class
starship heading this way
under impulse power.
Sending no call letters, sir.
The correct procedure...
What's wrong, sir?
Oh, it's nothing. Just a...
just a mild headache.
The correct procedure,
Ensign,
would have been
to signal the bridge of
your finding immediately.
Yes, sir.
Bringing it
here personally--
perhaps with the idea of being
on hand for the Ferengi
beam over,
might have
imperiled this vessel
had it been something
hostile approaching.
Yes, sir.
We are receiving
no signal at all
from the approaching starship,
sir.
Time, sir.
Time?
Oh, for the Ferengi beam over.
Do you see
any problem connected
with this old starship
coming in, Number One?
Suggest it would be safer, sir,
to have the Ferengi here
whatever happened.
Hmm, concur.
Stand by.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
Welcome in peace
to the Enterprise, DaiMon Bok.
It is our pleasure,
Captain Picard.
Might I introduce
my first officer, Kazago
and my second, Rata.
This is my first officer,
Commander William Riker.
Second in command, Data.
Counselor Troi...
We have heard that
you use females.
Clothed females!
Most interesting.
They are that, sir.
And the android
was mentioned, too.
What is its price?
We should like
to purchase it.
He is not for sale.
Commander Data
is, um... is, um...
Is secondhand merchandise.
You wouldn't want him.
Secondhand, sir?
Oh, of course,
a human joke.
Excuse me,
Captain.
But the unidentified
starship is coming in.
Still no signal at all.
Think nothing of it.
It is under our control.
One of our starships
under your control?
Do not be alarmed, Captain.
It is a gift from us
with which we honor
the hero of Maxia.
Who?
Why you, Picard,
of course.
Do you not remember
the Battle of Maxia?
I'm sorry. I do not
remember it, DaiMon Bok.
Data?
Captain, he may refer
to an encounter
which occurred nine years ago
in the Maxia Zeta star system,
in which an unidentified
starship...
Unidentified?!
That fine vessel was Ferengi.
Which you destroyed, sir.
The Battle of Maxia.
I've never heard it referred to
so dramatically before.
My sincere regrets, Bok,
but that vessel
refused to identify itself.
It simply attacked us.
We defended ourselves.
Such mistakes happen in space.
Hardly a mistake, sir.
Your report shows that
it deliberately attacked.
TASHA:
Do you want arriving vessel
on main viewer, sir?
It's only 1,000 kilometers
away now.
Put it on your viewer.
Main viewer.
There is no one aboard it.
The logs will be downloaded
into the Enterprise's
records...
at a price.
No price!
No price?
What is the purpose of this?
What...
I just felt
something too, Captain
Perhaps it is...
his conscience.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
No, no, I'm fine.
It felt as if... as if it were
something from your past.
It's all right.
I'm fine.
What is all this about?
It is about the battle
I mentioned, Captain.
A gift in honor
of that occasion.
Look at that ship closely.
Magnify please,
Lieutenant La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Why?
That's the Stargazer.
That's my old ship.
How did you find it?
It was a derelict.
Adrift in space
on the far side
of this star system.
How it got there
is none of my business, Captain.
But now that vessel
is yours
if you wish to have it.
We are not selling it
to him.
Consider it an act
of friendship.
At no cost?!
Oh, ugly.
Very ugly!
Captain's log, supplemental:
Bok and his officers have
returned to their vessel
inviting us now
to officially take possession
of the Stargazer.
Like before?
No, it hit with more impact.
Hit?
I'm sorry, but anything
could be important.
You said you felt
something yourself.
I believe so.
Like a thought but
rather mechanical in nature.
Are you sure it wasn't one
of my thoughts?
At that moment,
I was remembering
being at the helm
of the Stargazer.
A maneuver was being made.
We were hit.
Something's burning.
I can smell smoke.
Can you smell it?
There's nothing burning,
Jean-Luc.
That was just part
of my memory.
Memory or nightmare?
Well, it was strong,
whatever it was.
You ready, Number One?
Staff's waiting,
if Dr. Crusher approves.
I'll do better than that.
I'll go along.
We were traveling at warp 2
through the Maxia Zeta system
and this unidentified starship
suddenly appeared
and fired on us--
point-blank range.
RIKER:
Where did it come from?
It must have been lying
in some deep moon crater.
First attack damaged
the shields.
In the confusion, they hit us
a second time.
TASHA:
No clue who they were?
No names, no reason.
Can you identify them, Vigo?
If they come in
a second time
with our shields
damaged...
Sir, who's Vigo?
He's my weapons officer
on the Stargazer.
Hey, I'm getting quite
caught up in this.
Your shields were failing, sir.
Mm-hmm, I, uh, improvised.
With the enemy vessel
coming in for the kill,
I ordered a sensor bearing
and when it came
into the return arc...
You performed what Starfleet
textbooks now refer to as
The Picard Maneuver.
Well, I did what any good
helmsman would have done.
I dropped into high warp,
stopped right off
the enemy vessel's bow,
and fired with everything
I had.
And blowing into
maximum warp speed
you appeared for an instant,
to be in two places at once.
And our attacker fired
on the wrong one.
"I did what any good helmsman
would have done."
You did it first, sir.
It was a save-our-skins
maneuver.
We were finished, on fire.
We had to abandon ship.
We limped through space
in shuttlecraft for weeks
before we were picked up.
Well, I haven't thought
about this for years.
Sir, the Ferengi
are standing by
for us to take possession
of the Stargazer.
I want to go over to her.
I understand, sir.
As soon as my people have
made certain that she's safe.
And after I have another
look at you, Captain.
U.S.S. Stargazer.
Constellation class, Starfleet
registry N.C.C. 2893.
I activated the emergency
power cells.
Amazing they still work.
The rest of the ship is clear
of surprises, Lieutenant Yar.
You know, when I read about this
ship at the academy,
I never dreamed
I'd ever be on her.
Yar to Enterprise.
All clear, sir.
Hello, old friend.
You'll find this
most intriguing, sir.
What did you find, Data?
Last entry dated
nine years ago, sir-- by you.
"We are forced to abandon
our starship.
May she find
her way without us."
Apparently she did, sir.
How do you feel, Captain?
Oh, I'm fine, Doctor.
Lieutenant Yar,
run a structural analysis
on the Stargazer
for impulse tow.
Data, download all computers
to the Enterprise and file.
I'm... I'm going to look
at my old cabin.
Try this...
hero of Maxia.
No!
Captain.
Another headache?
This really worries me.
I want you back
on the Enterprise.
But my things.
I'll see they're sent
to your Enterprise quarters.
Enterprise now taking
possession of Stargazer, Kazago.
Permission granted, Riker.
Actually, it was
quite a bargain, Kazago.
I thought the Ferengi always
made a profit on things.
( snarl )
Set sub-warp speed
for towing, La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Starfleet has responded
to our request, sir.
A tug will rendezvous with
us and tow the Stargazer
back to Xendi
starbase nine.
Very well, Data.
How was it, Captain?
Very strange, Number One.
Like going back to the house
you grew up in
but no one's home
except phantoms
of the past.
It has troubled you.
Not half as much
as this damned headache.
Take over, Number One.
Aye, sir.
What's wrong?
I wish I could say.
Shields weakening, Captain.
Torpedoes armed.
Where are they?
Oh, my God, sir!
Fire.
Fire!
What is it, Data?
Why all the mystery?
The records
of the Stargazer, sir.
What the Ferengi call
the Battle of Maxia.
It seems the captain's
personal log contains
a much different version
of that conflict
than the official
historic account.
What are you saying?
It would appear
that the starship which
Captain Picard attacked
had in fact
been under a flag of truce.
What?!
And apparently, the captain
destroyed the ship
without notice
or provocation.
Impossible--
well, what about the fire aboard
the Stargazer?
An accident in Engineering.
And what proof?
It is logged
in his own voice, sir.
Would you care
to hear it, sir?
Sir?
This is a confession
given by me,
Jean-Luc Picard, commanding
U.S.S. Stargazer.
What does this mean?
I don't know, sir.
It sounds like your voice.
It is, Number One.
But I refuse to believe
you ever said that.
I admit I must have
mistaken their subspace antenna
for a weapon's cluster.
Unfortunately, I fired our main
phasers and our direct hits
destroyed the unknown vessel.
I've assumed they've
simulated your voice somehow.
I've already put Data
to work on it.
Thank you, Will.
I never made that log entry,
of course.
But it still leaves you
with a duty to perform.
I know, sir. I must
report to Starfleet.
That's at least
one full day
subspace communication
to reach there.
And one more full day
for their answer to return.
I'd like to have the truth
of this by then.
I'd hate to have to
prepare a formal defense.
I can't believe they'd
ask for your command.
Why wouldn't they?
With the Ferengi making these
friendship overtures,
I could become a severe
embarrassment to Starfleet.
I'm certain the Ferengi
are behind the fake log.
No wonder they're
waiting out there.
Headache back, sir.
Damn!
I'll call the doctor again.
There's no wonder with
all this going on.
Try to relax.
This is a confession
given by me,
Jean-Luc Picard,
commanding U.S.S. Stargazer.
In the hopes that
my belated honesty
will be taken into account
by Starfleet,
when judging my actions
during a confrontation
with an unidentified vessel...
Open hailing frequencies,
Geordi.
Opened, sir.
I'll take them in
the ready room--
Secure channel,
La Forge.
Secure, sir.
Starship Ferengi, this is
Commander Riker here.
I'd like to speak to
First Officer Kazago.
A problem, Riker?
Are our channels secure
on your end?
It is now.
Are you aware of the details
of the Battle of Maxia?
Captain Bok has just
made me aware of it, Riker.
The infamy of your Picard
is now fully known.
Infamy?
I would call
the wanton destruction
of an unarmed vessel infamy.
And if I produced evidence
that Captain Picard's
log entry was falsified
to indicate that--
I can hardly imagine
you contacted me
to discuss an ancient battle.
What do you want of me?
Just one question.
As you humans say,
"I'm all ears."
First officer to first
officer, Kazago.
If your Captain Bok
knew about this,
then why this peaceful
meeting to present us
with the Stargazer?
We freely give you back
your derelict warship,
and now you accuse us
of crime, Riker?!
I can bear no more insults.
Yes, who the hell is it?!
Not resting, Captain.
More like dying, Doctor.
Over here.
What is wrong with me?
I wish to hell
I knew, Captain.
But something unusual
has definitely been
happening to you.
The doctors always say
the obvious
as though it's a revelation.
Why do captains always
act like they're immortal?
No.
( chuckling )
You didn't tell me
it had been this bad.
It wasn't this bad,
but it's getting worse.
This should help a little.
It's got to be some kind
of emotional pressure
connected with the Stargazer.
I got this headache
long before I even knew
my old ship still existed.
Still, perhaps you're
partly right.
Want to talk about it?
I'm here.
A fight, Maxia.
I destroyed an entire vessel...
an entire crew.
Did you have a choice?
I don't know anymore--
I just don't know!
Commander Riker's told me
about the altered log
if that's what's troubling you.
The last three nights, I...
have heard these voices.
I'm on the bridge
of my old ship.
And there's fire all around me.
The klaxons, smoke...
and then I give the order.
And now the Stargazer is
really here.
And that that log...
Now am I going crazy?
How do I know I was
in my right mind at Maxia?
How do I know I'm in
my right mind now?
What was that?
Something to let you sleep.
Sleep...
Shields weakening, Captain.
Torpedoes armed.
Where are they?
( chuckling )
And now, my dear captain,
you are ready
to live the past.
Where did he come from?
Phasers, sir.
Sir?
Sir?!
What should we do, sir?
Should we fire back?
Fire, Captain.
Fire!
You will injure yourself
as you once injured me.
Sir!
Damage report.
Fusion generator under
surge control, sir!
Power systems failing!
Sensor beam bearing
on hostile ship!
7 mark 19, sir.
Phasers, sir?
Sir?
Ready phasers, and lock!
Stand by on warp nine.
Heading...
7, 7 mark 20.
Engage!
Steady...
Now! Reverse and stop!
Phasers fire! Torpedoes away!
Fire...
Fire.
By comparing the Stargazer's
main computer log
with Captain Picard's
personal log
I found checksum
discrepancies, sir.
What does that mean?
All information is
time-coded by entry.
And the bits, when totaled,
produce an aggregate amount...
I don't want a computer
science lesson, Data!
Bottom line?
One of these two logs is
a forgery, sir.
Correction.
The log just found aboard
the Stargazer is a forgery.
As I said.
That is one of them,
is it not?
Captain!
You are looking better, sir.
A little sleep,
thanks to the good doctor,
works wonders.
What report on the logs?
Yes, sir.
Whoever tampered with your
personal log was clever.
GEORDI:
But a bit clumsy.
It's definitely
a fabrication, sir.
Number One,
I'd like you to take a look
at this brain scan graph...
What are you doing here?
I thought I was captain
of this starship.
Of course you are,
but I...
Thank you for
the confirmation, Doctor.
But now, except for Riker,
I would like you all
to return to your stations.
Is that clear?
Sir.
You, too, Doctor.
I have business
with the commander.
Under protest, sir.
You have orders for me, sir?
Release the Stargazer from
the tractor beam, Number One.
Sir?
The tractor beam.
Sir, are you abandoning?
No. But her inertia will carry
the Stargazer along with us.
Or did you sleep
through the academy lecture
on the conservation of
tractor beam power?
No, sir.
I'll release her, of course.
BEVERLY:
Obviously there's some sort of
thought-process disorder here.
But I can't find
a physical reason for it.
Anything?
I'm puzzled, too.
I keep sensing random thoughts,
but two sets of them--
as if they were his, but
intermixed with other thoughts
which are also his.
I'm busy at the moment,
Wesley.
I know, Mom,
but this is important.
When I went back to the main
sensors in Engineering
to try some more sensitivity
experiments...
TROI:
Does this have to do
with Captain Picard?
Yes, ma'am.
If this is what
you're talking about here.
I don't know much
about brain scans.
But I glanced at these
when you were studying them
and I noticed that
these patterns are the same
as those picked up from
the low-intensity transmissions
from the Ferengi ship.
I went back and checked.
And they're exactly
the same.
What kind of transmissions?
I don't know.
Engineering has nothing
like it on record.
Let's get to the captain.
No, they might be
affecting the captain.
To Riker.
You're welcome, ladies.
Adults.
The captain, Commander?
Resting in his quarters
after ordering both of you to
return to your duty stations.
TROI:
There have been some...
Did he say low-intensity?
Mm.
Some unusual low-intensity
transmissions
from the Ferengi vessel.
Did who say?
My son.
Transmissions which exactly
match certain anomalies
found in the captain's
brain scans.
Something over there is
affecting the captain's
thought patterns.
Computer, give me a location
on Captain Picard.
Captain Picard is
in Transporter Room 3.
What?
Computer, emergency order
to Transporter Room 3.
New information.
Captain Picard is no longer
aboard the Enterprise.
Welcome back,
Captain.
What is happening?
Shields up,
computer.
What are you doing?
Collecting on an old debt.
Stargazer!
Captain, respond!
Shields up, sir.
No way to beam over any help.
Commander, I'm reading
something very strange here.
A low-intensity beam
of intermittent pulse
inside this starship.
I have a fix on it, sir.
Inside Captain Picard's
quarters.
You transferred some of his
belongings from the Stargazer?
Yes, including
a fairly heavy chest.
RIKER:
Go take a look, fast!
Commander...
the Stargazer is now
powering up, sir.
I have been waiting a long
nine years for this, Picard.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Do you not, human?
Can you not remember
the crime you committed
against my very blood?
You murdered my only son!
Your son?
He was commander of
the ship you destroyed
on his first voyage
as DaiMon.
The ship... the Ferengi
vessel that attacked me.
Or is it about
to attack me?
And I have spent
these years
searching, seeking,
a proper blood revenge.
And I found it!
I am rich, Picard.
Yet two of these
cost me the profits
of an entire life.
You are back in command
of the Stargazer, Picard.
These computers will
answer your orders.
Die well, Captain!
First Officer's log:
Captain Picard has beamed
himself to the Stargazer,
which is now moving away from
us under its own power.
Enterprise to Stargazer,
please respond!
Enterprise to Captain Picard
aboard Stargazer,
please answer!
Mr. Data, what was
Stargazer's condition?
Considerable fire damage
to interior surfaces
reported, sir.
But none of her main
systems are crippled.
Armaments, Lieutenant Yar?
Six photon torpedoes
short, sir.
Probably used when the captain
destroyed his Ferengi attackers
9 years ago.
Otherwise, fully armed.
What do you make of it,
La Forge?
Seems to be a network of
miniature circuitries, sir,
incredibly complex.
Maybe... maybe an amplifier.
Where was it in the captain's
quarters, Mr. Worf?
His chest from
the Stargazer, sir?
Just where I had left it,
he hadn't yet unpacked.
So he may not have even
known it was there?
And if this can pick up or
magnify thought-altering
transmission--
It could have prepared him
for whatever is happening now.
Let's find out... or try to.
Contact the Ferengi vessel,
Lieutenant.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
Enterprise to Ferengi vessel,
we transmit visually.
Do you respond?
Why is our gift to you
under power, human?
I will discuss that with
your captain.
He is working in
our ship's laboratory.
Where is your captain?
He's beamed himself aboard
the Stargazer.
And I'm wondering if this has
something to do with it.
How do you have
possession of that?
It was found in our
captain's chest,
which was brought over
from the Stargazer.
It is a forbidden device--
a thought maker.
If your captain is criminal
enough to own one--
Kazago!
You know who controls
those spheres.
Now I ask you again,
first officer to first officer,
what's going on?
It is not seemly to question
one's own DaiMon, Riker.
I am not prepared to do that.
Sir!
I have the Stargazer.
Switch, now!
Enterprise to Picard.
Do not attack again!
We are on a peaceful mission.
Give your identity!
You force us
to defend ourselves!
Phasers full up!
Arm torpedoes!
Why aren't the shields
at full power?
We've lost him, sir.
When he put up
the shields, sir.
Damn!
I said get the fusion
generators under surge control.
You're moving much to slowly!
Arm the torpedoes, man!
Vigo! Get a fire control
party up here!
Shields weakening, Captain.
Fusion generator online.
Weapons report!
Phasers coming
to full charge, sir.
Torpedoes armed!
Who are they?
Identify them!
They're turning for a third
pass at us, sir!
We can't take
another hit, Captain!
Sir?
I now feel anger
from our captain.
Fury over whatever it is
he is reliving out there.
The Battle of Maxia, sir,
that's what it is.
The Picard Maneuver!
What is the defense
against that, Data?
There is no defense, sir.
Then devise one, fast!
First Officer Kazago
to human Riker.
Not now, Kazago!
We do not wish to become
involved in what has
become clearly
a Federation matter.
Fine, fine!
Enterprise out!
You should also know
that DaiMon Bok no longer
commands this vessel.
His first officer has
confined him for
engaging in this
unprofitable adventure.
Good luck, First Officer Riker.
I have computed
a possibility, Commander.
Since even deep space
contains trace gases,
a vessel in the Picard Maneuver
might seem to disappear,
but our sensors could locate
any sudden compression
of those gases.
And use it as an aiming point
to blow our captain to bits?!
This class starship
has enough power to use
our tractor beam on it, sir.
Seize it, limit
its field of fire.
Right!
Concentrate shields
at that point.
Make it so!
I hope you're right, Data.
No question of it, sir.
Stand by!
Lock on tractor beam!
Ready phasers.
Captain Picard!
Listen to me.
Vigo, is that you?
It's Commander Riker, sir.
Captain, hear me!
Look around.
The Ferengi are using
their thought devices on you.
Stand by.
Who is this?
It's Riker, sir!
Your number one!
Look for a silver sphere!
Destroy it with your phaser!
Phaser...
Sphere...
Bok, used it.
Destroy it!
Phaser...
Destroy the sphere...
Destroy the sphere.
Are you all right, Captain?
Captain?
Captain! Are you all right?
Captain, are you all right?!
Where am I, Number One?
Aboard the Stargazer, sir.
The sphere you destroyed,
it's been controlling your--
Bok!
Where is Bok?!
Removed from command, sir.
And placed under guard for his
act of personal vengeance.
Seems there was
no profit in it.
In revenge there never is.
Let the dead rest.
And the past...
remain the past.
Enterprise, lock on.
Beam me home, Riker.