Captain's Log,
Stardate 41590.5:
Having dropped off
Counselor Troi
at Starbase G-6
for a shuttle visit home
we were fortunately close
to the Sigma III solar system
when its Federation colony
transmitted an urgent call
for medical help.
An accidental explosion
has devastated
a mining operation there.
Include a burn unit
with each kit.
Upon arrival, identify the most
critically injured
and beam them up to Cargo Bay 6.
PICARD:
Dr. Crusher,
this is the Captain.
Dr. Crusher here.
Additional information.
The number of colonists
at the site is 504.
Are you prepared for that many,
Doctor?
We believe so, sir.
Captain, we are now
at warp 9.1, sir.
Which will bring us to the
colony in 3.2 hours, sir.
Captain, I have a schematic
from the explosion site.
It suggests the cause may
be a methane-like gas
seeping in
from underground.
Captain,
I'm picking up
a force field out there
of some kind. It's almost...
( alarm blaring )
The Q entity, sir.
It is identical
to the grid we
encountered when...
It reads solid, sir.
Emergency, full stop.
Reversing power, sir.
Not now, damn it, Q.
Shields and deflectors up, sir.
( electrical crackling )
Now reading
full stop, sir.
Q:
Humans, I thought by now that
you would have scampered back
to your own little star system.
If this is Q I'm addressing
we are on a mission of rescue to
aid a group of badly injured...
We of the Q have studied
our recent contact with you
and are impressed.
We have much to discuss
including, perhaps,
the realization
of your most impossible dreams.
However intriguing
that may be, Q
we are in the midst
of an urgent journey.
Once that is completed,
then perhaps...
You will abandon that mission,
Captain.
My business with you
takes precedence.
If my magnificence
blinds you...
then, perhaps,
something more familiar...
Starfleet Admiral Q,
at your service.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
Our rescue mission
to the Sigma III solar system
has been halted
by an immense grid
and an untimely visit from Q.
You're no
Starfleet admiral, Q.
Neither am I an Aldebaran
serpent, Captain
but you accepted me
as such.
Well, he's got us
there, Captain.
Ah, the redoubtable Commander
Riker, whom I noticed before.
You seem to find this all
very amusing.
I might... if we weren't
on our way to help
some suffering
and dying humans...
Aw, your species is always
suffering and dying.
PICARD:
No, Lieutenant Worf!
You'll make no move against him
unless I order it.
Pity.
You might have learned
an interesting lesson--
macro head
with a micro brain!
( growling )
You said you had the realization
of impossible dreams
to offer us?
When this rescue is completed
I am prepared to listen
carefully
to whatever proposal you wish
to make, and subject
to its being
acceptable...
Subject to your own foolish
human values?
Oh, come, Picard.
Why do you distrust me so?
Why?
At our first meeting,
you seized my vessel
you condemned all humans
as savages
and, on that charge,
you tried us
in a post-atomic
21st century
court of horrors
where you attacked my people.
You again seized my vessel...
And that angered you, did it?
"Seized my vessel,
seized my vessel..."
You interfered
with our Farpoint mission.
You threatened to convict us
as ignorant savages
if, while dealing with
a powerful and complex life-form
we made the slightest mistake,
and when that didn't happen...
The Q became interested
in you.
Does no one here understand
your incredible good fortune?
"Seized my vessel!"
These are the complaints
of a closed mind
too accustomed
to military privileges.
But you, Riker--
and I remember you well--
what do you make of my offer?
We don't have time
for these games.
Games?
Did someone say games?
And perchance
for interest's sake...
a deadly game?
To the game.
RIKER:
Where are we?
Obviously a class-M world--
gravity and oxygen,
within our limits.
Twin moons.
Where are we?
Considering the power
demonstrated by Q
the last time...
anywhere--
assuming this place even exists.
But it won't be boring.
If Q is anything,
he's imaginative.
Apparently our Captain
wasn't meant to be here with us.
Security, this is the Captain.
Security?
Engineering, this is the Bridge.
( fritzing beeps )
Turbolift control, do you read?
This is the Captain.
Sir, over there!
Join me, Riker.
A good game needs
rules and planning.
Wasn't it your own Hartley
who said
"Nothing reveals humanity
so well as the games it plays"?
Almost right.
Actually, you reveal yourselves
best in how you play.
Sir, what he has in mind
might provide us
with vital information.
Ahh...
Incredible.
I was just thinking
about an old-fashioned lemonade.
And so it became that.
An excellent
thirst quencher.
Gets rather hot out
here on this plain.
What about my people?
Whatever they'd like,
of course.
( glass breaks )
"Drink not
with thine enemy."
The rigid Klingon code.
Explains something of
why you defeated them.
You're still fascinated
with the human past?
Perhaps you're not
that original.
Au contraire!
It's the human future
which intrigues us
and it should concern
you the most.
You see, of all
the species
yours cannot
abide stagnation.
Change is at the heart
of what you are.
But change into what?
That's the question.
That is what humans
call a truism.
You mean,
hardly original?
You're the one
who said it.
While we're at it
this isn't part
of any human future.
True.
I borrowed this
from your stodgy
Captain's mind.
This is the dressing
for a game that we will play.
Now, games require rules
and rewards
and dangers and familiar
settings, that sort of thing.
This isn't that familiar to me.
Data?
This is from Europe's
Napoleonic era, sir--
late 18th,
early 19th centuries.
This is a campaign
headquarters tent.
His uniform is that
of a French
army marshal.
And a marshal outranks
even an admiral.
Well, you think I would go
from a Starfleet admiral
to anything else?
Of course you wouldn't.
But Napoleonic equipment
on an alien planet?
One so different
it has twin moons?
Well, as you've said, I'm
nothing if not imaginative
and the game
should reflect that.
Shall it be a test of strength?
Meaningless,
since you have none.
A test of intelligence, then?
Equally as meaningless.
But it needs risk!
Something to win...
and something to lose.
If we must play a game,
what would we win?
The greatest possible future
that you could imagine
which of course requires
something totally disastrous
if you're to lose.
Now, the point of
this game shall be
can any of you stay alive?
If your game is fair, we will.
Oh, for shame, Worf!
Fairness is such
a human concept.
Think imaginatively.
This game shall, in fact,
be completely unfair.
You've gone too far.
Game penalty!
Where is she, Q?
You can forget your game...
To use a 20th century term
she's in a penalty box
where she will
remain unharmed
unless one of you
merits a penalty.
Unfortunately,
there's only one penalty box.
If any of you
should be sent there
dear Tasha must give the box up
to you.
And where does she go?
Into nothingness.
I entreat you to carefully
obey the rules of the game.
The only one who can destroy
your Tasha now
is you.
( electrical crackling )
Captain's Log...
( voice slows and fades):
Captain's... Log...
Damn it!
I can't even
make a log entry.
I wish I could
help you, Captain.
Where is everyone else?
Down on some planet.
Some planet?
What are you doing here?
Well, I, uh... uh...
It sounds strange...
but I'm in a penalty box.
A penalty box?
Q's penalty box.
It sounds strange
but it definitely isn't.
I know that one more penalty
by anyone
and I'm gone.
Gone?
Yes, I am gone!
( crying softly )
It is so
frustrating
to be controlled
like this.
Lieutenant...
Tasha...
it's all right.
What in the hell
am I doing?
Crying?
Don't worry.
There is a new ship's
standing order on the Bridge.
When one is in the
penalty box, tears
are permitted.
( laughing )
Captain...
Oh, if you weren't a Captain...
Q:
Consorting with lower rank
females, Captain?
Especially ones
in penalty boxes?
Destructive to discipline,
they say.
But then again,
you're what?
You're only human.
Penalty...
over.
A marshal of France?
Ridiculous!
Well, one takes
the jobs he can get.
For example,
Starlog entries.
Stardate today.
This is
Q speaking
for Captain Jean-Luc Picard
whom we consider to be too bound
by Starfleet customs
and traditions
to be useful to us.
The Enterprise
is now helpless
stuck like an Earth insect
in amber
while its bridge crew
plays out a game
whose real intent is to test
whether the first officer
is worthy
of the greatest gift
the Q can offer.
So you're taking
on Riker this time.
Excellent.
He'll defeat you
just as I did.
Shall we wager
on that, Captain?
Your starship command
against...
Against your keeping
out of humanity's path...
forever!
Done?
Done!
And you've already lost, Picard.
Riker will be offered
something impossible to refuse.
Geordi,
can you see Worf?
I'd see the freckles
on his nose
if he had them, sir.
He's at the third ridge.
The third ridge?
Mmm-hmm.
Moving well, too.
Uh, oh.
Good, he sees them.
( snarling and snorting )
Listen to me, Q.
You seem to have
some need for humans.
Mmm... Concern
regarding them.
Well, whatever it is
why do you demonstrate it
through this confrontation?
Why not a simple,
direct explanation--
a statement
of what you seek?
Why these games?
Well, the play is the thing.
And I'm surprised
you have to ask
when your human Shakespeare
explained it all so well.
So he did, but don't
depend too much
on any one single viewpoint...
It's a pity you don't
know the content of
your own library.
Hear this, Picard
and reflect:
"All the galaxy's a stage..."
World, not galaxy--
"all the world's a stage."
Oh, you know that one.
Well, if he were living now
he would have said galaxy.
How about this, uh...
"Life is but a walking shadow.
"A poor player that struts
"and frets
his hour upon the stage
"and then is heard no more.
"It is a tale
told by an idiot
"full of sound
and fury
signifying
nothing."
I see.
So how we respond to a game
tells you more about us
than our real life--
this "tale told
by an idiot".
Interesting, Q.
Oh, thank you very much.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Perhaps maybe
a little Hamlet?
Oh, no, I know Hamlet.
And what he might say
with irony
I say with conviction.
"What a piece of work is man!
"How noble in reason.
"How infinite in faculty.
"In form,
in moving
"how express
and admirable.
"In action,
how like an angel.
"In apprehension
how like
a god."
Surely you don't see your
species like that, do you?
I see us
one day becoming that, Q.
Is it that
which concerns you?
Those soldiers have formed
a skirmishing line
I think
you'd call it.
And they're
headed this way.
Armed with ancient
ball-and-powder muskets?
That's what their weapons
look like, sir.
Muskets are
appropriate
to the 1790-1800
French army uniform, sir
but it is
hardly a weapon
by our standards.
A lead ball
propelled
by gunpowder.
100 meters at best
with any accuracy.
Yeah, but against phasers?
Just one
of our hand phasers
could finish off
an entire regiment.
Except for one thing.
That hardly sounds
like Q--
to give us an advantage
like that.
Unless...
Drop your weapons!
I'm afraid
that was me, Worf.
I was checking to see if
the phasers still operate.
Incredible, Worf!
You came
out of nowhere.
A warrior's reaction.
Report.
What did you find?
Sir, what they're wearing
may be old Earth uniforms
but what's inside
of them isn't human at all--
more like vicious animal things.
( snorting and snarling )
Those soldiers
are moving in fast, sir.
Data, if you've got a theory
about what's
happening...
Think fast, Commander Riker.
And move fast.
( phaser blast )
Those aren't muskets!
Q:
You have only one chance
to save them now.
Send them back
to the ship.
You'll let me
beam them?
Send them the same way I do.
I've given you the power.
Do you understand?
I have given you
the power of the Q.
Use it.
( enemy phaser blast )
Q:
Use your power.
Lieutenant,
take the conn position.
Engineering, this is the Bridge.
Engineering here, sir.
Engineering, are all
systems back on line?
Back on line, sir?
They were never off.
Captain, you'd
better look at this.
There's been no interruption
in course or speed.
Both have
remained constant.
It's as though
we never stopped.
We never did,
Lieutenant.
Q suspended time.
Where's Commander Riker?
He was with us.
GEORDI:
He must still be
on the planet.
We were under
attack by these...
these animal things.
Animal things?
Well, maybe Data could
explain it better, sir.
You may find it
aesthetically
displeasing, sir.
I could just file
a computer report on that.
Data!
Sir, the important
thing right now is
why is Commander
Riker missing?
Understood, Lieutenant.
But I suspect that
Commander Riker is
probably perfectly safe
at least in a
physical sense.
Q has an interest
in him.
In fact,
Q's entire visit
has something to do
with our first officer.
And the reason
for that, sir?
I wish
I knew.
Q first became interested
in him at Farpoint.
I have no idea
what it means.
Meanwhile, we must proceed
with our rescue mission.
( Riker laughing heartily )
Something
amuses you?
Perhaps you'll share
the joke with me?
The joke is you.
Strange gratitude from one
who has been granted a gift
beyond any human dream.
How can you
not appreciate
being able to
send your friends
back to their ship?
Or send the soldiers back
to the nothingness
from which they came?
Certainly you must understand
that at this moment
you can send yourself
back to the ship
or to Earth, or
change your shape
and become anything
you want to be.
What do you need, Q?
Need?
You want something
from us, desperately.
What is it?
Want something
from you foolish,
fragile non-entities?
Oh, come, Riker--
you're beginning
to sound like
your Captain.
Now, that's a compliment, Q,
but that's not an answer.
Riker, we have offered you
a gift beyond all other gifts.
Out of the goodness
of your heart?
After Farpoint, I returned
to where we exist--
the Q continuum.
Which means exactly what?
The limitless dimensions
of the galaxy in which we exist.
I don't understand.
Of course
you don't
and you never will
until you become one of us.
"Until"? Would you mind
going over that again?
Well, if you'd stop
interrupting me...
I mean, this is hardly a time
to be teaching you
the true nature of the universe.
However...
at Farpoint,
we saw you as savages only.
We discovered
instead
that you are
unusual creatures
in your own limited ways--
ways which, in time,
will not be so limited.
We're growing?
Something about us compels
us to learn, explore.
Yes, the human compulsion.
And unfortunately for us, it is
a power which will grow stronger
century after century
eon after eon.
Eons.
Have you any idea
how far we'll advance?
Perhaps in the future
that you cannot yet conceive
even beyond us.
So, you see,
we must know more
about this human
compulsion.
That's why we've selected you,
Riker, to become part of the Q.
So that you can bring to us
this human need and hunger
that we may better
understand it.
I suppose that's meant
as a compliment, Q.
Or maybe it's my limited mind.
But to become a part of you...?
I don't even like you!
You're going to miss me.
Come on, not again!
Commander Riker,
what's going on?
I was sitting
in school and...
TASHA:
Worf!
My phaser's gone.
Are you armed?
No.
Where is Q?
If you have an answer
to any
of this...
( trumpet sounds "advance" )
( drumming )
Worf!
RIKER:
Look out!
PICARD:
Wesley, no!
Wesley!
RIKER:
No, damn it!
Damn it to hell!
Riker!
You...
you did that.
And that's not all.
That grid,
their wounds...
only the Q
can do that.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41591.4:
12 minutes out
from Quadra Sigma III
where the survivors
of an underground disaster
desperately need our help.
Aboard the Enterprise
First Officer William T. Riker
needs help nearly as badly.
But this is a subject
far out of my experience--
out of any human's experience.
Will...
How the hell
do I advise you?
You know the
implications
as well as I.
No one has ever offered to
turn me into a god before.
What the Q has offered you
has got to be close
to immortality, Will.
They're not lying
about controlling
time and space.
We've seen it in
what they can do.
You've also seen it
in what I can do.
If you're going
to refuse his offer
you must not allow yourself
to use this power again.
It's too great
a temptation for us
at our present stage
of development.
Are you worried that I won't
be able to say no to it?
You tell me.
Are you strong enough to refuse
to use that power?
Certainly!
No matter how tempted?
No matter how difficult
Q makes it for you?
You have my word.
Good.
I know what
your word means.
DATA:
In orbit
of Quadra Sigma III, sir.
Ready to beam down rescue team
to underground emergency area.
This way, sir.
( coughing and moaning )
Are there any others?
Gone.
It's just us.
Commander!
There's somebody
under here.
GEORDI:
You're getting
close, Data
It's too late...
she's dead.
If only we'd gotten
here a little sooner.
Sir, if indeed you have
the power of Q...
I don't understand.
Certainly you can't
bring her back to life?
I can't.
I'm prevented from that
by a promise.
I should have never have made
that agreement with you.
I could have saved
that child.
You were right not to try.
Once you became accustomed
to that power, Number One...
When I used
it before
what happened?
I saved most of our Bridge crew.
And when you grow
to like it too much?
As soon as
it's convenient, Captain
I want a meeting with you
and your Bridge staff.
As soon as we are secure
of this rescue operation
I'll discuss all
that this
new power...
We can confer here
on the Bridge
if no one has
any objections.
The Bridge
will be fine
since I've called
the entire staff.
Correction, Number One--
knowing the decision you face
I've permitted you
this gathering.
Of course, Jean-Luc.
Wesley
this meeting
is not for you.
Why not, sir?
You helped make me
a Bridge officer...
acting ensign.
All right, he stays.
Because I've been
given unusual powers
I'm not suddenly a monster.
Except for these abilities--
and I don't yet know
how far they go--
I'm the same William T. Riker
you've always known.
Well?
Everyone
still looks uncomfortable.
Perhaps they're all remembering
that old saying
"power corrupts...
...and absolute power
corrupts absolutely."
Do you believe I haven't
thought of that, Jean-Luc?
And have you noticed how you and
I are now on a first name basis?
Number one...
Will...
something has happened already.
In what way?
Haven't you seen
how much I regretted
not saving that child?
Using the power
of Q to save her
may not have been wrong.
No more than it was wrong
to save the rest of you
from those
soldier things.
Let's keep in mind that
that particular danger
was invented by Q.
TASHA:
What we represent
to the Q, Commander
are lowly animals,
tormented into performing
for their
amusement.
Actually, they think very highly
of us, Tasha.
We have
a quality
of growth
which they admire.
Or fear.
No, we've learned
the Q do not admire us.
The Q
has muddled your mind.
Don't you understand
his incredible gift to me?
Q:
Are these
truly
your friends,
brother?
Let us pray
for understanding
and for compassion.
Let us do no such damn thing!
What is this need of yours
for costumes, Q?
Have you no identity
of your own?
I come in search of the truth.
You come in search
of what humanity is!
I forgive your blasphemy!
Can't you see,
Riker?
He's nothing
but a flimflam man.
He's been that ever since
we met him at Farpoint.
Flimflam?
You offer Riker jealousy.
What I offer him is clearly
beyond your comprehension.
How can you claim friendship
for Riker
while obstructing his way
to the greatest adventure
ever offered
a human?
Obstructing him?
Then it's not yet certain?
He's not yet
committed?
The truly evil part of all this,
Captain, is your jealousy.
You love each one
of your people.
Demonstrate it.
You have
the power
to leave
each of them
with a gift proving
your affection.
There'd be no harm, would there
if I gave them something
I know they'd like?
Oh, how touching.
A plea to his
former Captain.
"May I please give happiness
to my friends, sir?
Please, sir."
In fact, I authorize and support
your idea, Riker.
Please feel free to cooperate
with him, if you wish.
Are you certain, sir?
Quite certain,
Data.
By all means, demonstrate
your gifts of affection.
Don't be frightened.
There is no way
I could harm any of you.
Shall I guess
your dreams?
Leave now,
Wesley.
No, Wesley I may
know best of all.
Our friendship,
our long talks...
No, please.
Have your favorite wish,
my young friend.
RIKER:
You're ten years older--
a man.
Hey, Wes...
not bad.
Data.
No!
No, sir.
But it's what
you've always wanted, Data--
to become human.
DATA:
Yes, sir.
That is true.
But I never wanted to compound
one illusion with another.
It might be real to Q--
perhaps even
you, sir--
but it would never be so to me.
Was it not one of the Captain's
favorite authors who wrote
"this above all,
to thine own self be true"?
Sorry,
Commander.
I must decline.
And you, my friend...
I know what you want.
You're as beautiful
as I imagined.
And more.
Then we can
throw away the visor?
I don't
think so, sir.
The price is a little
too high for me
and I don't like who
I'd have to thank.
Make me the way I was.
Please!
RIKER:
Proud warrior Worf
without a single tie
to his own kind.
( growls )
( seductive growl )
No!
She is from a world
now alien to me!
Worf, is this your idea of sex?
This is sex.
But I have no place for it
in my life now!
No place, micro brain?
What possesses you?
( growling )
Commander Riker,
it's too soon for this.
If this is because your mother
objects...
WESLEY:
No.
I just want
to get there
on my own.
Honest.
But it's easier, boy.
Listen
to Riker.
How did you know, sir?
I feel like such an idiot.
Quite right.
So you should.
It's all over, Q.
You have no further
business here.
Human, you have
just destroyed yourself.
Pay off
your wager.
I recall no wager!
I'm sure
your fellow Q remember
that you agreed
never to trouble
our species again.
Just as they're aware
that you failed
to tempt a human to join you.
No! No, if I could do
one more thing!
Q, I strongly suspect
there's some explaining
you have to do now.
No!
Extraordinary.
Captain, we are showing
that same hole in time again.
Our instruments
say we just now
beamed back
from our rescue mission.
Sir, how is it that the Q can
handle time and space so well
and us so badly?
Perhaps some day
we will discover
that space and time are simpler
than the human equation.
No coordinates
laid in, Number One?
Yes, sir.
You have my
coordinates,
La Forge?
Aye, sir.
On the board.
Engage.