Captain's Log,
Stardate 41294.5:
Our destination:
the class M Beta Cassius planet
known simply as Haven.
It is a world so renowned
for its peaceful beauty
that some believe it to have
mystical healing powers.
We will rest and relax...
all too briefly, I fear.
Such a beautiful world.
Legends say it has been
known to mend souls
and heal broken hearts.
Legends which are totally
unsupported by fact, Captain.
Legends like that are the spice
of the universe, Mr. Data,
because they have a way
of sometimes coming true.
( harp music )
Lieutenant Yar
to Commander Riker.
Your presence is requested
in Transporter Room One.
Sorry, ladies.
Duty calls.
You needed me, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
There's an object of some
kind beaming in from Haven.
What is it?
We're not sure.
The surface station approval
coming in now, Lieutenant.
All right.
Let's bring it in.
Odd-looking.
What's going on?
( gasp )
I hold a message
for Deanna Troi.
Lwaxana Troi
and the honorable Miller family
will soon arrive.
The momentous day
is close at hand.
Rejoice!
( laughing )
No.
What's going on?
( clattering )
Jewels... Look at these jewels.
They're bonding gifts...
what you would call
wedding presents.
Who's getting married?
I am.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I was certain it would
never happen, Captain--
the years I'd spent
on this mission...
the distance it has
taken me from home.
As you must have heard,
genetic bonding
is a Betazoid tradition.
Steven Miller was my
father's closest friend.
Your father was human, Deanna.
The Millers are human.
Will you and your husband
be staying with the ship,
Counselor?
No, sir.
Then...
I'll just say...
congratulations
for now, Deanna.
If you'll excuse me.
Will...
more than anything
in the world--
anything--
you want to be
a starship captain.
True?
That's not all I want, Deanna.
I can feel that.
I know you care,
within those limits.
Did you hear what I said?
Every word.
This whole thing
is still bizarre.
I'm sorry.
Come dance at my wedding.
I'll try.
Message from planet
Haven, Counselor.
They wish to beam the Miller
wedding party aboard.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard,
Captain of the Enterprise.
Welcome aboard.
Quite some starship
you have here, Captain.
I look forward to this visit.
You couldn't be!
I'm Deanna.
Oh, Deanna, darling!
You probably don't
even remember me.
Oh, Wyatt was
absolutely right.
She is a beauty.
I'm Wyatt.
Isn't this
simply beautiful?
I knew romance was
still alive somewhere.
I'd like you to have this.
It's a chameleon rose.
It changes color with the mood
of its owner.
It's wonderful.
Thank you.
When is
my mother arriving?
Your mother is still
down on the planet, Deanna.
Why?
Uh, is there is place
for my parents to rest, Captain?
Well, uh, we're not really
tired, son.
Besides...
I'd like to see
some of the ship.
Steven, you know full well
Lwaxana Troi isn't about
to beam on board
until we leave.
So...
You can see your quarters
now, if you like.
Will you show the Millers
to their accommodations, please?
And I shall join you later.
Two more are ready
to beam in, sir.
So be it.
Wyatt seems
a fine young man.
Yes, he does.
But I'm not
what he expected.
I don't understand.
Neither do I,
but I'm definitely a surprise
of some sort to him.
I should warn you, sir...
my mother is a little...
eccentric.
Where is everyone?
Oh, I hate that.
Hello, Mother.
No, don't say it, think it.
Use your mind, not your mouth.
Hello, Mother.
Deanna, shame!
What has this life done to you?
No, no, no.
Don't tell me.
You're the Captain.
Of course.
Your daughter has explained
your telepathic abilities.
No, that wasn't telepathy--
it was just common sense.
Who else would greet me
but the Captain?
You may carry my luggage.
Mother!
No, no,
that's quite all right.
I'm indebted to your mother
for the fine Counselor she's...
This way.
Mother, it's quite inappropriate
to ask the Captain...
Yes, you do seem to
be having difficulty.
A man your age must work
to keep himself in shape.
Mother, I'm not going
another step like this.
A starship has its customs
just as we do.
If you're my mother's valet
then please valet!
Oh, please, don't let me
keep you from doing your duty.
I apologize
for her behavior.
Do you realize you've
embarrassed your Captain?
Oh, no.
Anything to avoid
a quarrel
on this occasion.
It's amazing
how that accent of yours
reminds me of your father.
Your last valet tried
so hard to rid me of it.
Whatever happened
to Mr. Xelo?
Oh, I was forced to
terminate his employment.
Xelo was strongly
attracted to me.
His thoughts became truly
pornographic.
Of course, the thoughts
of Wyatt's father toward me...
Passenger accomo...
...were almost as vulgar,
but he really doesn't have...
Passenger accommodations.
He doesn't really
have Xelo's imagination.
Mother...
Between him and that
woman's inane chatter
it's a wonder
I made it here at all.
How do you like
the Millers, Captain?
Oh, I'm sure I find them
perfectly pleasant.
As for me,
I find it shocking
how they have changed
in the years
since my husband
and I knew them.
Of course, it's probably
because I've grown beyond them.
You realize, of course,
that with Betazoids
our ability to read
the thoughts of others
does see us grow much faster
than the typical plodding human.
Mother, that's enough!
So, you're not totally
out of practice.
Good, very good.
We hope you find
the room comfortable.
Ah, yes.
The room is adequate.
Small, but adequate.
You will, of course,
adjust the temperature
to a civilized level?
Ah, I'll see what I can do.
And now,
if you will excuse me.
I'm sure the two of you
have a lot to talk about.
Oh, yes, Captain.
You may go.
You've been slack, little one.
Allowed your mental powers
to rust.
Only to avoid
confusion, Mother.
Humans constantly think
one thing and say another.
Yes, they do, don't they?
Poor dears.
Our style of complete honesty
frightens them.
On that subject, Mother,
there is such a thing as
too much honesty with humans.
If they'd only say
what they think
instead of hiding it.
An entire shipload
of such inconsistency
could drive one insane.
Darling, I'm terribly sorry
about what happened here.
Truly I am.
Steven Miller
tracked me down
and reminded me
of the vows we had made.
Mother, I'm having
some trouble
believing in those
vows as once I did.
Deanna...
But I'll honor them,
of course.
I'm a Betazoid.
You may find Wyatt
an unusual person.
I've sensed remarkable
depths in him.
Message coming in
from Haven, Captain.
On screen.
I'm Valeda Innis,
first Electorine of Haven.
Captain Picard?
Greetings, Electorine.
I'm Picard.
Your presence honors us
and your timing
is fortuitous, Captain.
In what way?
An incoming vessel
has bypassed our Stargate
violating our law.
It has refused
any attempt at communication.
Are you saying
you believe it to be hostile?
Failure to communicate
is inherently hostile.
We have no defensive
capabilities here
and our treaty
with the Federation
specifies your obligations
in that matter.
Agreed.
But let's hope it doesn't
become a defense matter.
Of course, Captain.
But I am very happy
we have you here.
( door chime )
Come in.
I wanted to apologize
for my mother's behavior.
Your mother's honest.
I respect that.
Yes, but she
never lets up.
I'll admit her honesty
is a bit persistent.
I never heard
it described better,
but it is a Betazoid trait.
I'll try to be
only half as annoying.
Let's see...
what can I tell you
about myself?
I'm a medical doctor,
for whatever that's worth.
Doctor?
If you're picking up
my thoughts, you'd know.
You can do that, can't you?
Sometimes.
This must be what
Mother felt about you.
I believe we could read
each other eventually.
Can I take that
as a compliment?
Absolutely.
I only ever felt this...
Well, with, um,
someone who's on this ship.
Oh.
Do I have competition?
No.
What he wants most
is to captain a starship.
What I want is
to cure people.
Well, I'm a practicing
psychologist.
Maybe we could work
in concert.
We are going to be together a
long time.
Yes.
That is the point
of marriage, I suppose.
I really thought
you'd tell me
you were an artist.
I just felt your mind
very much on these.
They are your work,
aren't they?
I can see it would
be very hard
to keep secrets from you.
This is why you
were surprised
when you first saw me.
This woman...
you thought I would be
this woman.
I have seen this face
ever since I was a boy.
When I close
my eyes at night
I could hear her
whispering my name.
And knowing you
were Betazoid,
I just assumed it was you
projecting yourself
into my mind.
I'm sorry I'm not
what you hoped for...
No.
Please don't mistake
a childish fantasy
for disappointment.
You are so beautiful.
I feel honored.
You've no idea who she is?
It doesn't really matter now.
Captain's Personal Log:
I trust my concern
over the problems
of ship's Counselor Troi
are not based merely on losing
a highly valuable crew member.
But it seems to me
that she is trapped
by a custom of her homeworld
which the facts
of 24th-century life
have made unwise
and unworkable.
I wish I could intervene.
On the viewer, Captain.
Unidentified vessel
traveling at sub-warp speed.
Bearing 235.7.
Sub-warp?
It's several hours away then.
Let's take a look at it.
Enlarge to maximum.
Increasing magnification, sir.
Mr. Data, is that
the trouble I believe it is?
If you mean
a Tarellian vessel, sir,
it is.
I thought the Tarellians
were all dead.
What are the poor devils
doing here?
Picard to Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher to Bridge.
Urgent.
They must not be permitted
to destroy us
or the planet.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
It has been believed the
Tarellian race was extinct,
an assumption
contradicted now
by the sight of one of their
vessels approaching Haven.
The fact that it's traveling
at its present velocity
suggests a possible answer.
A damaged vessel, sir.
That could explain it.
If it was unable
to reach warp speed
it would have taken
all these years to get here.
Go on with your
briefing, Mr. Data.
Tarella was class M,
much like your Earth
with similar
humanoid life-forms.
Unfortunately,
they faced the old story
of hatred overpowering
intelligence.
PICARD:
There were hostilities?
Between the inhabitants
of their two land masses
resulting in one group
unleashing a deadly biological
weapon on the other.
And in the end, the other
becoming infected as well.
It makes one question
the sanity of humanoid forms.
Can you identify the origin
of the infection, Doctor?
The Tarellians
had reached Earth's
late 20th century
level of knowledge.
That's all you need
if you're a damned fool.
A deadly infectious virus,
which, at that modest level
of knowledge,
is not difficult to grow.
We learned the rest of
the story in security training.
Some Tarellians made
it to other worlds
only to die along with
populations they infected.
It's pretty well covered in
Academy training now, Captain.
Many of them tried to avoid
other civilized worlds
as they escaped,
only to be hunted down
and destroyed anyway.
Hmm... and it was believed
that the last Tarellian ship
was destroyed eight years ago
by the Alcyones.
Yes, sir.
Exactly when will
they reach Haven?
Exactly 13 hours, nine minutes,
22 seconds, 350...
Thank you.
Which creates a very difficult
problem for the Enterprise.
Our treaty requires us
to protect Haven
and Federation policy
requires
that we assist
life-forms in need...
which must include
the Tarellians.
I shall want you
to help me find some answers.
Thank you.
However,
there will be ample time
for your second assignment--
voluntary, of course--
the pre-joining announcement
of Counselor
Deanna Troi...
...and Wyatt Miller.
We've talked it
over, Captain,
and the ceremony will be
tomorrow, if you agree.
And, Captain,
would it be possible
for you to perform
the ceremony?
Well, yes, of course,
if all parties request it.
All parties
do not request it.
It's simply out
of the question.
I'm sorry, Captain,
but unfortunately,
you are not practiced in
the ways of Betazed joining.
No, that's quite true.
Therefore, you are
totally unqualified.
He is qualified to lead
a traditional Earth ceremony
which is what
this will be.
Here, I thought you had
no sense of humor.
An Earth wedding?
Ridiculous.
My family and I
are living on Earth now.
So, that's why you want
that backward ritual.
Terrible, Captain, to see
a woman go downhill like this.
Mother!
Downhill?
The matter is settled.
Mr. Homn will
conduct the joining.
But... but Homn
can't even talk.
No matter.
He is highly adept
in act of sign language.
The matter is closed.
Who are you to tell us
what we should do?
Your ignorance is astonishing.
I am Lwaxana Troi,
Daughter of
the Fifth House,
Holder of the Sacred
Chalice of Rixx,
Heir to the Holy Rings
of Betazed.
Who are you?
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is a Starfleet tradition
that at social
gatherings
disputes are
not permitted.
I hereby declare, therefore,
all disagreements resolved.
Here, here.
A toast:
to the young couple
and their families.
And?
And may this union be
a productive one.
Here, here.
Considering the rate
at which you imbibe, sir,
is your lineage
at all mixed with human?
Is it true, Captain,
that there's a Tarellian ship
headed for Haven?
( gong sounds )
Yes, it is true.
WYATT:
That's amazing.
I've read everything
I could about them.
Biological virus
analysis was
a favorite subject
at medical school.
In which case, I'd very much
like to confer with you.
I'm pleased to have
a medical colleague on board.
WYATT:
Yes, ma'am...
...um, Doctor.
( gong sounds )
Would it
be possible
to prepare some
medical needs geared toward
the Tarellian probable needs?
We could beam it over
without any fear of infection.
What do you think,
Doctor?
( gong sounds )
It's a very
considerate idea.
Our Sick Bay is at
your disposal, Doctor.
Thank you.
Mr. Data.
Sir?
You're circling the room
like a buzzard.
Perhaps being human
yourself, sir,
you do not find them as...
( gong sounds )
...intriguing as I.
Must he do that?
As you well know,
it is the Betazed way
of giving thanks
for the food we eat.
You, giving thanks?
Besides, you never
did this before.
I do it now.
Unlike some people,
I am in growth.
Victoria,
I've forgotten whether
you enjoy pets or not.
Love them, of course.
Good.
( chittering )
( screams )
Gently, gently.
Poor baby,
did she hurt you?
Captain, if you'll excuse me
I'd like to spend
some time considering...
the Tarellian situation.
Yes, of course.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Mrs. Troi,
I'm very interested in the
Betazed ceremony you mentioned.
Could you tell us more?
Why, I'd be delighted,
Commander.
It's an ancient ceremony
widely regarded as the most
beautiful in the universe.
After the young couple
have removed their clothing...
The bride and groom go naked?
All guests must
go unclothed.
It honors the act of love
being celebrated.
( coughs )
No, you needn't
worry too much, dear.
Your body's
not that bad.
Besides, your husband
quite likes the idea
of seeing me unclothed.
Steven!
Oh, you did know
he's attracted to me,
didn't you?
Untrue. I don't...
Stop this petty bickering,
all of you!
Especially you, Mother!
( gong sounds )
Could you please continue
the petty bickering?
I find it most intriguing.
May I join you?
I will miss you, Deanna.
I am no longer Imzadi to you?
You taught me that word
means "my beloved."
And the human heart
is too small
to permit that
feeling now?
Have you discussed
this with Wyatt?
I think you should.
It's also
damned unfair to me.
I understand.
I should have realized.
Humans, young human
males particularly,
have difficulty separating
platonic love
and physical love.
The problem is...
Imzadi...
I couldn't.
Not now.
Call it an old...
an old Earth tradition
habit of the beasts...
whatever.
Hello, you two.
We were just talking
about you, Wyatt.
This is incredible!
Yes.
And in that discussion, I...
Actually...
Bill was concerned
that you might be upset
that I cared deeply
for him, too.
Oh, you're the one who wants
to be a starship captain.
Yes, I've heard that
bonding or marriage
would complicate
things in that case.
To each his own.
Good luck with
that ambition.
And I very much respected
what you did tonight.
All I did was lose my temper.
If you'll excuse me.
Of course.
Running all this
is a big job.
In fact, you shamed them
into compromise.
So they've decided
that the joining will be
half Betazed, half Earth.
The Captain will
do the ceremony
and Mr. Homn will
be my best man.
And we'll take
half our clothes off?
Some of us still go naked.
You do.
I do.
Your mother,
my father,
but not my mother
or the guests.
Captain Picard will be
very relieved.
How did you manage it?
Your mother relented.
And I just caught my father
practicing naked
in front of his mirror.
( laughing )
And, so...
a question I should
have asked before...
Deanna, do you really want
to go through with this?
Yes.
I want to.
I'm a very lucky man.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
All attempts at warning off the
Tarellian ship have failed.
They still refuse
to communicate
and I'm growing concerned.
How can you be certain
they're receiving us?
Because our sensors are
showing a responder echo, sir,
on the frequency
they once used.
We have a message, sir,
coming in from Haven.
On viewer.
Captain, the plague ship is
approaching transporter range.
PICARD:
We are aware of
that, Electorine.
Do you realize
that they can turn
this wonderful world of ours
into a graveyard?
Please!
Please take action now,
before it's too late.
We recognize your situation.
Please destroy them now!
We will not fire on them,
Electorine.
You must!
I'm certain I could
disable their ship
with a phaser
burst, Captain.
And then, Lieutenant?
DATA:
They're within
transporter range, sir.
Then we can't delay
any longer.
Ready the tractor beam,
Lieutenant Yar.
Target the ship.
Activate on my command.
Tractor beam ready.
Engage.
Got them, sir.
Do we have them securely,
Lieutenant?
Can they beam onto the planet?
Negative, sir.
They can't leave that ship.
I know they can
receive us, Captain.
At this distance,
they could respond
with running lights
if necessary.
Unless they
have all died.
Their ship could have been
brought in by automation.
Captain!
It's the woman
in Wyatt's drawings.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41294.6:
Orbiting Haven
with a Tarellian vessel
locked in our tractor beam.
Question: what strange
combination of circumstances
has caused a woman
out of someone's imagination
to appear on the plague ship?
Enterprise to Tarellian vessel,
are you receiving us?
My name is Wrenn.
And before I inquire
why your tractor beam
has trapped us here,
is there one aboard
your vessel named Wyatt?
Captain, I don't understand.
It's astounding.
Ariana was right.
He is here, daughter.
Wyatt, you've come
just as you promised.
How could I be so accurate?
Except for the dream images,
I've never seen her.
Sir, our concern
is with the threat
your vessel poses
to the planet below
if you're still carrying
the infection that
destroyed your world.
Oh, we still
carry it, Captain.
My daughter, I...
all eight of us.
Eight?
All of us that
are left, Captain.
Most of the rest passed on
during the years
that it took to reach Haven.
If you've come here
because of the legend
about planet Haven
miraculously healing the sick...
We don't ask to make contact
with those living below.
All we ask is to be
on the edge of some sea,
some unpopulated island
or far away peninsula.
This is not
our planet, sir,
but I will present
your needs
to those who do
govern this world.
Present the fact that we intend
to die here, Captain.
And if we die while caged
by your tractor beam...
so be it.
( door chime )
Oh, Wyatt, how do you like
my new hairstyle?
Of course, it's going to
look much better on me
when I'm naked.
Mrs. Troi, may I talk to you
about something serious?
Oh, but I'm always serious,
dear boy.
Only my pleasant nature
makes it appear otherwise.
Please, Mrs. Troi!
Yes, that was puzzling.
A woman out of another place
who insists
that she knows you.
And...
And whom you've dreamed of
all these years.
And I was hoping the way
you handled thoughts...
Fascinating, Wyatt, how easily
your thoughts come through.
The answer to the puzzle
of Ariana and you is so simple.
It's too simple for
most humans to understand.
Too simple?
Of course.
It's something they all
know instinctively
yet go to great effort
to reject
or build complicated
superstitions about.
All life, Wyatt,
all consciousness
is indissolubly
bound together.
Indeed, it's all part
of the same thing.
Yes!
I have wondered
if something like that...
...that weren't so.
And no doubt
so has Ariana,
which helped the two of you
to make contact.
Wyatt, tell me
something seriously.
Which of these would
look best on me naked?
Wyatt.
Are you feeling
all right?
Just wedding nerves.
The supplies are ready.
I'll take them
to the transporter room.
I'll notify
the Captain they're ready.
VICTORIA:
Look at your father, Wyatt.
He just can't wait to
strip off his clothes
for that barbaric
ceremony.
Please take care
of each other.
You are beautiful...
but you looked the best of all
in the desert on the Holodeck...
when we did this.
You can put
the supplies on the pad.
Dr. Crusher had me
set the coordinates.
All we need is
the Captain's order.
Captain, someone's transporting
over to the Tarellian ship.
Override.
I can't, sir.
It's too late.
Hello, Wyatt.
We always thought
you were a dream.
You're not surprised.
Did you know I'd beam over?
Once we saw you were real,
we knew.
You are a doctor.
Yes, I've brought
medicines and supplies.
And I knew you
would be this brave.
How could you
let this happen?
My son surrounded by
those horrible lepers.
Mrs. Miller, if I could have
prevented this, I would...
Beam him back.
He can never come back,
Mrs. Miller.
You may turn off
your tractor beam, Captain.
We will not be going to Haven.
We have what we
really came for.
Wyatt!
Mother, Father...
forgive me, but I must...
I'm going to try to continue
the work to cure these people.
And Wyatt will do it.
I've believed
that all along.
I knew I was coming to Haven
to meet my destiny.
I thought it was
to be with you, Deanna,
but it was Ariana
who drew me here.
I'm sorry.
Wyatt, I'm happy for you.
And for Ariana, too.
You've done very well
for a human, Wyatt.
Mother.
Captain... my respects.
And mine, sir.
Good-bye.
Keep the chest.
You'll have use
for it someday.
Oh, it seems such a shame
to waste the whole trip.
Perhaps I should stay
and be joined to a new mate.
What?
Well, the Captain is
highly attracted to me,
but he's a
little too old.
Perhaps I should choose you.
He has other obligations,
Mother.
Oh, very well.
It's his loss.
Mr. Homn.
Thank you
for the drinks.
Try and remember
your heritage, little one.
Captain! Even Xelo never had
such thoughts about me.
You may energize.
That was meant
as a joke, Captain.
I was not amused.
Take us out of here, Mr. Riker.
Aye, sir.
Warp two, helm.
Heading 5-7, mark 3-1-9.
Our destiny is elsewhere...
but I'm happy that yours
is here with us, Counselor.
Warp two, sir,
heading 5-7,
mark 3-1-9.
Engage.