First Officer's Log,
Stardate 41997.7:
We are about to make
a brief but necessary contact
with the Jarada
a reclusive, insect-like race
known for its idiosyncratic
attitude toward protocol.
The Jarada demand
a precise greeting
in this case
from Captain Picard.
Their language
is most unusual.
The slightest mispronunciation
is regarded as an insult.
PICARD:
Unless it's
followed by...
The double bars indicate
an elongated "s" sound.
And the inverted "t" means
to hold the "z".
Unless?
Unless it's followed
by three wavy lines
in which case the "z"
becomes a "b."
Exactly.
What a language!
But you spell "knife"
with a "k."
I spell knife
with an "n."
But then I never
could spell.
Well, this is
an insect mind, sir.
My mind is barely working.
Take a break.
No, no, I want to go
over this again.
You could be over-preparing.
You've been looking forward
to the upgrade of the holodeck.
You have the time.
Captain, you need the diversion.
Dixon Hill.
The program's installed
and waiting.
Program desired location.
Earth, United States,
San Francisco, California.
Time period?
1941 AD.
File or access code?
File Dixon Hill,
private detective.
Enter when ready.
Captain's Personal Log:
I'm entering
the ship's holodeck
where images of reality
can be created by our computer.
Highly useful
in crew training.
Highly enjoyable when used
for games and recreation.
Very funny, Dix.
What did you do,
lose another bet?
I'm sorry,
I don't understand.
The bellboy suit.
Are you moonlighting
at the Fairmont?
The uniform?
It's totally inappropriate.
I should have changed.
Detective Bell
your cop friend
McNary's new partner
was here nosing around.
If he'd have seen you
in those threads
he'd have had you sent
to the funny farm.
Mr. Leech
called twice.
and there's a lady named
Bradley waiting in your office.
Nice legs.
Not you, her.
Got a hot date
with my fella.
See you in the morning.
I lost a bet.
Oh, well, at least you're
ready for Halloween.
Halloween?
I need your help, Mr. Hill.
Someone is trying to kill me.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Personal Log:
I am delighted
with how the holodeck
has created the fictional world
of Dixon Hill
the twentieth century detective
who's been a hero of mine
since childhood.
The characters
are meta-generated
by the computer, of course
yet they feel real.
They seem real in every way.
I'm not sure
who wants me dead--
my husband,
my stepdaughter...
Or a lover, perhaps.
Perhaps.
Or perhaps
it's Cyrus Redblock.
I need you to find out.
Name your fee.
$20.00 a day,
plus expenses.
Agreed.
I haven't said yes yet.
Oh, you'll say yes,
Mr. Hill.
If it is Redblock, he must think
I've got what he's looking for.
But believe me, I don't.
I'll take
your word for it.
Here's a C-note,
in advance.
Consider it a retainer.
And next time, wear a suit.
Au revoir.
( horn honking outside )
Remarkable!
Exit.
( knocking )
You'll have
to call again.
I'm just leaving.
I'm not dressed properly.
I'll be back.
Mr. Hill?
Where are you?
Memory, save current setting.
Current setting saved.
Holodeck off.
And when I looked down
into the street
I actually saw automobiles.
Otto-moveels?
Mm-hmm.
An ancient
Earth device
used primarily
for transportation.
Ah.
Also seen as a source
of status and virility.
Often a prime ingredient
in teenage mating rituals.
Teenage mating rituals?
From that window, I
could see an entire...
City block?
That's right.
Sounds, smells...
You make it sound so real.
That's how it felt.
Incredible.
Hmm?
Oh.
Well, I'm going
to go again.
Only this time, I'm going
to dress the part.
Why not come with me?
Yes, I'd like that.
I want to take that
20th century historian...
Who, Whalen?
Yes, Whalen.
I bet he knows more
about Dixon Hill than I do.
Shall I
tell him, sir?
Invite him, Mr. Data.
This is supposed to be
a recreational activity.
The sense of reality
was absolutely incredible.
When that woman kissed me
it was so...
Exciting?
Real.
The purpose of this meeting
is to discuss
the Jaradan rendezvous.
Mr. Riker, will you go ahead
with the briefing?
This is primarily
a diplomatic mission.
The Jaradan are strategically
important to the federation.
Previous attempts have failed
because they are
so easily irritated.
A slip in the pronunciation
of the greeting
caused a 20-year rift.
The Captain has to recite
the entire greeting
without making any mistakes.
Simple as that, huh?
DATA:
Yes.
If, on the other hand,
the Captain makes
even the
slightest
error...
The Captain
is well aware
of the gravity
of the situation, Commander.
We are all aware of the tape
of the last Federation starship
to come into contact
with the Jaradan.
It graphically
demonstrates
what happened when that
Captain offended them.
Captain Picard
is familiar with
that, Data.
Should we not rerun it?
It's not necessary, Mr. Data.
Meeting adjourned.
Why would the Captain
not want to review
all available information
on the subject?
Data, when you've seen
the Jaradan react once
you don't ever need
to see it again.
This Dixon Hill is
a most puzzling character.
Not really.
He was just a 20th century
Sherlock Holmes.
Ah, but was his
modus operandi
not dissimilar?
Worth investigating.
Indubitably, my dear Data.
Indubitably.
Computer, request all
biographical information
on fictional character
Dixon Hill.
Working.
Character first appeared
in pulp magazine
Amazing Detective Stories,
copyright 1934 AD.
Second appearance in novel
The Long Dark Tunnel
copyright 1936.
Request complete text
of all stories
involving said character.
Increase speed.
Captain's Log, Supplemental:
The Jaradan rendezvous
is still 11 hours away.
I am about to reenter
the world of Dixon Hill--
this time, properly dressed.
An experience like this
is more enjoyable when shared
so I've invited
our fiction expert, Whalen
to accompany me.
Dr. Crusher will
join us shortly.
Ready for San Francisco,
Mr. Whalen?
More than ready, sir.
Well, if it's anything
like last time
I'm sure you won't
be disappointed.
Permission to accompany you,
sir.
I am totally versed
in the genre of the period.
Well, shall we?
( horns honking )
Hey, Dix, how's Tricks?
Hmm? Oh, she's fine, fine.
Wonderful. He actually
thinks you're Dixon Hill.
Say, Mack, I would like
to buy a newspaper, too
but I don't have
any money.
Hey, you catch me next time,
huh, Dix?
Thank you,
thank you.
"Hitler
on the move.
"Roosevelt presses
Congress for British aid.
( mispronounces ):
DiMaggio streak
reaches 37."
DiMaggio, sir.
Jolting Joe,
the Yankee Clipper.
Baseball, sir.
It was a national
obsession at the time.
The streak they are referring to
will eventually reach 56 games
and be
snapped
by a pair of journeyman hurlers
for the Cleveland Indians.
Cleveland?
They got no pitchers,
they never got no pitchers.
What are you, nuts or something?
The record
will stand
until the year 2026
when a shortstop
for the London Kings...
Hey, Dix, what gives
with this guy?
He's not from around here,
is he?
No, he's not.
He's...
he's from...
South America.
Yeah, he's got a nice tan.
I should have
listened to her.
She told me someone
was trying to kill her.
Captain, she's a page
from a book.
That's all she ever was.
Well, well.
Look what the cat
dragged in.
Cat?
Where the hell did he come from?
South America.
Can't you tell?
Wherever you're from
while you're in my town
you keep your nose clean.
Well,
tough guy
this time you've really done it.
Your goose is
cooked, but good.
I'm sorry
about this, Dix.
Don't apologize
to him.
Where were you last night
between 10:00 and midnight?
That would be a bit hard
to explain.
Yeah? Well, you'll have
plenty of time
to come up with something.
You're going downtown.
For what?
For the murder
of Jessica Bradley.
We found this
in her purse.
Status report.
We're being probed, sir.
The Jarada.
Most likely.
But it's
long range.
Can't be certain
where it's originating.
One could get the feeling
they don't exactly trust us.
Commander, I'm receiving
a subspace message
from the Jarada.
That's not part
of the plan.
Pipe it through.
Enterprise, we speak to you
in your language.
The time has come
for you to honor us in ours.
This is Commander Riker,
First Officer of the Enterprise.
You are not Captain?
No, sir, I'm not.
I suggest we commence
screen-to-screen communication
so we can see each other.
You offend us.
We will not show ourselves
to a mere subordinate.
We await your Captain's greeting
with growing unrest.
End of communication.
Terrific.
Find the Captain.
He's in the holodeck.
Aye, sir.
Enter when ready.
...when ready.
Hiya, Doc.
What's cooking?
You know I had some trouble
getting through?
Where's
Captain Picard?
He's on ice.
Pardon?
He's being grilled.
What is he, a fish?
He's being interrogated.
They think
he committed a murder.
Why aren't we all
being interrogated?
Maybe I should go and help him.
No, no, no, relax.
Relax, doc.
He's having the time
of his life in there.
Well, why should he have
all the fun?
Come on, Toots,
let's go.
Spill it.
I've told you
everything I know.
Well, you'll just have
to tell us again.
From the top.
From the top!
Oh, very good.
I've read all
this before, you know.
It's absolutely
as it should be.
La Forge to Bridge.
Riker here.
I can't find the Captain, sir.
I told you,
he's in the holodeck.
I'm at the holodeck.
Something's gone wrong.
What are you saying, Lieutenant?
I can't communicate with them.
I can't access the program
and I can't open the doors.
Enterprise Log, Supplemental,
First Officer reporting:
Due to a breakdown
in the holodeck
we are unable to contact
the Captain.
Tasha, take over.
I'm going to holodeck 3.
WESLEY:
Commander.
I've studied all the technical
manuals on the holodeck, sir.
I think I can be
of some help down there.
Geordi's well equipped
to deal with the situation, Wes.
Right now your duty's here
on the Bridge.
Will, his mother's
missing, too.
Come on, Wesley.
And you say you
never met her
before she came
to hire you.
I've already told you
that, twice.
Yeah? Well, you're going
to have to tell me again.
Look, fellows, this
is no longer amusing.
Easy, Dan.
You think you're
tough, Hill
but you're nothing!
Don't take him
too seriously, Dix.
His old lady's been
giving him a hard time.
You know how it is.
Actually, I do need
to get out of here.
I'll see
what I can do.
( clears throat )
Something on your mind?
Yeah, but
I'm not sure
it can be repeated
in mixed company.
You're a pretty
hep-looking broad.
Is that good?
It ain't bad.
You like
Tommy Dorsey?
I got two tickets
for the dance
tomorrow night.
Have you tried the intercom?
GEORDI:
Yes.
Riker to holodeck.
Are you seeing anything?
No, sir.
RIKER:
What can I do?
GEORDI:
Not a thing.
We have to go
through this
millimeter
by millimeter.
All right,
get it fixed.
Easy, Wes,
slow it down.
If there's
an anomaly
you could go right
past it, okay?
I've known the guy
for ten years.
Okay, Dix, we're
cutting you loose.
That's
welcome news.
You better not try
to leave town.
If I leave town,
the town leaves with me.
I get the feeling your friend
doesn't like me.
We know you're dealing
with Redblock, Dixon.
Take it
from a friend.
It doesn't
help your case.
Redblock?
I'll keep it in mind.
Thank you
for helping me.
Forget it.
( coughs )
Say, Dix, when you
coming over for supper?
The kids would
love to see you.
And you know how much you
love Sharon's cooking.
Soon, my friend.
For the moment,
I have other duties.
Blonde or
brunette?
She's a lady,
all right.
And her name
is Enterprise.
Sounds like a working
girl to me.
Hey, I'll stop by the office
with a bottle of scotch.
You can tell me all about her.
Have a good time?
I don't know.
Sometimes it almost
seemed too real.
I must say,
you wear it well.
I'm glad you
could make it.
Why, thank you,
Mr. Hill.
Maybe we should
be getting back
to the Enterprise.
We are
on the Enterprise.
Oh, yes, of course.
So we are.
Do we have time
to see your office?
Mmm. Yes, of course.
Why not?
Captain, mind
if I join you?
Yeah, me too,
boss.
I'd love
to take a gander.
The holodeck makes excellent use
of finite space.
Oh, Mr. Hill, you have
been avoiding me.
It's Felix Leech.
It has to be.
You know me, sir?
Well, I've read about you,
many times.
I'm very sorry, Mr. Leech,
but we have to be going.
Call again tomorrow.
You're being quite rude,
Mr. Hill.
You haven't even introduced me
to your charming companions.
That'll have
to wait.
But we have business.
Urgent business.
You're not
going anywhere.
Not until we have
a little chat.
YAR:
Bridge to holodeck.
We're approaching
the Jaradan sector.
RIKER:
Any word
from the Jaradans?
Not a thing, sir.
They may be testing us--
seeing if we'll stick
to the arrangements.
What do we do now, sir?
We wait.
Well, everything checks
out so far.
Ensign Crusher believes
the trouble
may have been caused
by the Jaradan probe.
If so, it could be
very difficult to locate.
I am not a man
to be toyed with, Mr. Hill.
You were hired to locate
a certain
object.
I demand to know
what you have
done with it.
Well, I suppose
a few moments longer...
I'm afraid I can't
help you, Mr. Leech.
The game
is over.
I assure you,
this is not a game.
Take it from me, Leech.
You'll never find it.
Now give me the gun.
( gunshot )
But they're not real.
There's massive internal
bleeding.
We have to get him
to sick bay.
How could
this happen?
It will happen again
if you don't cooperate.
Ooh!
You struck me.
How dare
you?
You're going
to be sorry.
I promise
you.
Redblock isn't going
to like this!
If we don't
get him to sick bay,
he will die.
Exit.
Computer, exit!
Data, try the other
exit in the hall.
Computer, identify exit.
There's a programming
malfunction.
The computer refuses
to identify the exits.
I'm losing his pulse.
Computer, this
is the Captain!
Computer,
identify exit!
Standard orbit,
Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
Standard orbit.
Riker to holodeck.
Nothing yet, Commander.
We're running out of time.
The Jarada will expect
the Captain's greeting.
Well, you may have
to stall them.
It's no use.
It's just not there.
Suggestions,
Mr. Data.
I'm at
a loss, sir.
We're in a holodeck-created
building of 1941.
The computer refuses
to accept voice commands.
The controls for the environment
are therefore not accessible.
I could use some light.
( door opens )
Good day, Mr. Hill.
My name is Cyrus Redblock.
I hope you don't mind us
dropping in.
I see I have no choice.
Life is an endless stream
of choices.
Unfortunately,
you have chosen
to make my life
more difficult.
I don't suppose you'd be
foolish enough
to hide it here?
I don't suppose so.
Still, I'm sure
you won't mind
if we take a look around?
I wish you'd quit asking,
since it's obvious
you're going to do it
anyway.
It's just
a waste of time.
Good manners, madam, are never
Civility, gentleman.
Always civility.
Get that stiff
out of here.
He's not dead.
From his pallor,
he soon will be.
You want I should throw him
in the garbage, boss?
The room next door will be
good enough for now.
Don't touch him.
Which one struck you?
It was Hill.
For every action
there is an equal
and opposite reaction.
A Newtonian truism which
you have obviously neglected.
McNARY:
Dix, you
in there?
I saw your light
and figured you were
working late.
Guess I was right.
Nice company you're
keeping, Dix.
You forget to take
the trash out this morning?
I'm a tolerant man
but I do not tolerate
disrespect.
Your devotion to etiquette
is highly admirable, sir.
However, your methods
leave much to be desired.
What have we here?
LEECH:
He looks
like a ghost.
Yeah.
Where do you
suppose he's from?
Where were you
hatched, anyway?
I was created on a planet...
Data.
South America.
REDBLOCK:
I've been
all over the world.
I've never seen
anything like you.
He's not from this world.
None of us are.
We are from a world...
we're from a world
of fabulous riches.
A world where there are objects
far greater
than the one you seek.
That's ridiculous.
You're a private dick.
We've met before
and you never even mentioned
any of this.
He's right,
Dix.
That's pretty weak stuff.
I wouldn't even buy
that line of guff.
I am not Dixon Hill.
I just look like Dixon Hill.
DATA:
He speaks the truth, sir.
From your point
of view
he is only a facsimile.
A knock-off.
A cheap imitation.
Thank you, Mr. Data.
Sorry, sir, that
did not come out
quite the way
I intended.
REDBLOCK:
Very, very good.
What wonderful
fiction.
Quite entertaining.
I admire
your skill
at trying to obfuscate
our sense of reality.
It is you who
are not real, sir.
CRUSHER:
Data...
It's you who are
imaginary characters
derived from a
work of fiction.
Give it up,
fellas.
These guys are
too smart
to fall for that
kind of story.
I am afraid you are not
real either, Lieutenant.
LEECH:
I don't want to hear
any more of this.
You're making me crazy.
Let me shoot them, Mr. Redblock.
Let me kill them
one by one.
What an interesting situation.
Perhaps we should test
this theory
by killing
one of them.
You've already done that.
This man is dying.
It's all so senseless.
Oh, hardly.
Senseless killing is immoral,
but killing for a purpose
can be quite often ingenious.
Well said, Mr. Redblock.
What is our purpose?
We are on a quest
for knowledge, Mr. Leech.
We want the item!
We don't have it.
Shall I kill him?
No.
Kill the woman.
Redblock.
I have the item.
At last.
I knew it.
God, man, what a
character you are.
Waiting till
the last moment.
Testing my resolve.
All right.
Where is it?
I'll explain.
But first tell Leech
to back off.
Put the gun down, Mr. Leech.
But I so much
want to kill her.
Maybe later.
It won't harm us
to listen to Mr. Hill.
Don't make
any deals
with that slime, Dix.
All right,
let's begin.
Make your thoughts fruitful
and your words eloquent,
'cause I don't
have to tell you,
your lovely lady friend's life
depends upon it.
There is a price.
By god, I knew you were
a man of my stripe.
All right.
What is it?
Mr. Whalen's life.
You must help us to save him.
We can't delay
much longer.
We're going to have
to tell them something.
Open hailing frequencies.
Frequencies open, sir.
This is Commander Riker
aboard the Enterprise.
We demand that you...
( loud buzzing )
Cut that off.
They're not going
to be satisfied
with anyone less
than the Captain.
La Forge to Bridge.
Riker here.
We think we have something, sir.
I'll let Ensign Crusher explain.
The bi-converter interface
has been affect...
Forget the explanation!
Can you do it?
I don't know if I should, sir.
If this isn't done correctly
the program could abort
and everyone inside
could vanish.
Do you need more time
to study it?
Whether we do it now or later,
the risk is the same.
Do it.
If we can find a way of getting
him to our sick bay
by fixing our computer...
Computer?
I don't know that word.
An electronic
or mechanical apparatus
capable of carrying out
repetitious
or complex mathematical
operations at high speed.
Computers
are used to control,
process, perform,
or store...
Enough!
Let me kill him.
He's really beginning
to irritate me.
(overlapping shouting)
(overlapping exclamations)
Captain--
the exit.
That's it.
That's the way
into our world.
Remarkable.
Is this a two-way passage?
Can one enter your world
and return
to this one
simply by
stepping
through?
Oh, yes.
Allow us to help
Mr. Whalen
and we will return with...
the item.
You really are
a scamp, aren't you?
Do you actually think
I'd stay here and...
If you were going to go
through yourself, sir
that is not possible.
One look
at you, sir
is proof that anything
is possible.
Step aside, Mr. Hill.
I'd shoot
you myself
but I don't want to deprive
my assistant
of his greatest pleasure.
After we're gone
kill them all.
Make sure the bodies
are never found.
You're insane.
You think you can kill
a cop and get away with it?
Why not?
I've done it before.
Come on, Mr. Leech.
Au revoir
et bon chance, mon ami.
Our destiny awaits.
Another world.
A whole new world
to plunder.
What is this?
What are they doing?
They can't
do this to me!
Don't they know
who I am?
I'm Cyrus Redblock!
Cyrus Redblock!
With your permission, sir?
Permission granted.
Data, pick up Whalen.
Take him to sick bay.
And you, sir?
I'll follow.
You go now.
I wish I could
take you with me.
Someone has
to book this creep.
Once a cop,
always a cop, I guess.
I have to go.
So...
this is the big good-bye.
Tell me
something, Dix.
When you're gone
will this world still exist?
Will my wife and kids still be
waiting for me at home?
I honestly don't know.
Good-bye, my friend.
Captain.
RIKER:
You ready, sir?
Ready as I'll ever be,
Number One.
Open hailing frequencies.
Frequencies
open, sir.
This is Jean-Luc Picard,
Captain of the Enterprise.
( Jaradan greeting )
You have honored us
with your words of greeting.
A new day dawns
between us.
(cheers and applause)
So...
have a nice vacation?
It was a nice place
to visit, Number One
but I wouldn't want
to die there.
So, Data,
how was it?
It was raining in
the City by the Bay--
a hard rain.
Hard enough
to wash the slime...
Data!
Sorry, sir.
Lieutenant, take us
out of orbit.
Aye, sir.
And Mr. La Forge...
Sir?
Step on it.