Captain's Log,
Stardate 41242.4:
Our last assignment
has taken us
into the remote
Omicron Theta star system
home of our android crew member
Lieutenant Commander Data.
Although we are due
at our next assignment
I have decided
to visit Data's home planet
for a few hours
in the hopes of unraveling
some of the mystery
of his beginnings.
Sir, we are now 20 minutes
from Omicron Theta.
Mark.
Stand by for subwarp.
Head for standard orbit
of Data's planet.
I wonder why Data
hasn't come up here.
He said he wanted
to be alone.
Perhaps this is
a bigger moment for
him than we thought.
Ah...
ah...
Data.
...choo!
What are you doing?
Sneezing.
Have you got a cold?
A cold what?
It's a disease my mom
says people used to get.
Ah...
but humans still sneeze
for other reasons
and I cannot seem
to do it right.
Ah... ah...
How can you be practicing
something like sneezing
when we're arriving
at your home planet
for the first time?
Aren't you interested
in that?
More than interested--
fascinated.
One might say agog.
But I also find
sneezing interesting.
Choo!
Chh...
Captain Picard wishes
to see you on the Bridge.
YAR:
Captain, confirming Class M
reading there, but...
but the sensors aren't showing
any life readings...
not even vegetation.
Strange.
The cruiser that found Data
reported farmlands there.
Do you want to take her
into orbit, Data?
No, thank you, sir.
Continue on
into close parking orbit.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
I could say "home
sweet home," sir
if I understood
how the word
"sweet" applies.
It usually refers to memories.
It usually refers
to one's own memories, Captain.
Do the memories you have
include farms, Data?
Affirmative, sir
but the colony's
principal interest
was science.
YAR:
Data, I don't understand
how you can hold
the memories of 411 people
if that means every experience,
every day of their life...?
It does not,
unfortunately.
It means only the knowledge
they had accumulated.
Actually, I'm quite deficient
in some basic human information.
Sneezing, for example.
Sneezing?
Approaching close parking orbit.
Assemble your away party,
Commander.
This must be an exciting
time for you, Mr. Data.
I'm tempted to lead
the away team myself
except that my first officer
would object.
How would Starfleet
judge me if I didn't?
An entire Earth colony
did disappear down there.
You see?
Now in close parking orbit, sir.
Mr. Data...
welcome home.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 4124.5:
We have found Data's home
to be a completely dead world
down to lifeless vegetation.
No insects--
not even soil bacteria.
What is it
that could kill everything
on an entire planet?
Recording signal locked
onto the Enterprise, sir.
This looks like anything
but farmland.
Agreed, sir.
The soil appears almost
completely lifeless.
This is the exact position
in the Tripoli log.
Do you recognize
anything, Data?
The land contours
are familiar, sir.
Topographically,
this is the correct area.
This once was rich farmland
I'd say something like
20 to 30 years ago.
I was discovered
26 years ago.
Commander, I'd say that
everything on this planet
was either dead or dying
at the time Data was found.
I was found 20 meters
in that direction, sir.
YAR:
Data, any idea at all
why you were given
the colonists' memories?
I've always felt
that it was done hurriedly
but I know little more.
Here, sir.
This is where the cruiser's
landing party
found the signal device
that led them here.
And they found
me lying there.
You were just lying
out there in the open?
No identity record,
no instructions?
Only a layer of dust.
What's the first thing
you remember, Data?
Opening my eyes...
looking into the eyes
of the Tripoli landing party.
They believed
that the signal device
sensed their presence
and activated me.
Then this very spot
was your birthplace.
LA FORGE:
Commander.
I think I've got
this place figured out here.
This was very cleverly done
to make this look
like a natural hollow
in the terrain here.
There are signs of it
being constructed in a hurry
as if to hide something here.
Yes, that was it, Geordi.
This awakens
a memory remnant
of how the colonists
hoped to remain hidden
but their fear
of being discovered
led to their storing information
in me.
Yeah, thought so.
( lights powering up )
No life readings
in here either, sir.
The colonists' laboratory--
extremely well-equipped.
Does this stir
any memories, Data?
Only a vague impression
of some of my functions
being tested here.
Posted by proud parents?
It depicts something
that feels familiar, sir
and dangerous
but I have no idea
what it represents.
And that is all
except...
for an impression
of this
being a Dr. Soong's work area.
Who?
You don't mean
Dr. Noonien Soong?
He was called
that here,
but his memories indicate
he traveled here
under a different name.
Dr. Noonien Soong,
my friend,
happens to have been
Earth's foremost
robotics scientist.
Until he tried
to make Asimov's dream
of a positronic brain
come true.
A positronic brain...
He promised so much
and then when he failed
completely,
Dr. Soong disappeared.
Now we know he went somewhere
else to try a second time.
Data, Geordi, we'll get
a close look at this lab.
You and Lieutenant Worf
reconnoiter
where those corridors lead.
Aye, sir.
LA FORGE:
Data, it's you.
RIKER:
An epidermal mold--
made to give your exterior
the desired finish.
Lieutenant Yar
to Commander Riker.
Come in, Lieutenant.
Sir, this installation
is big enough
to hold hundreds of people,
but all that's here now
is empty beds.
Thank you,
Lieutenant.
Complete your record scans
and report back here.
LA FORGE:
Commander Riker, looks like
some sort of storage area.
How many more
Datas are there?
Looks like just these two.
I mean, that and the real Data.
Commander...
can this be another me?
Or possibly my brother?
I honestly don't
know, Data.
He needs assembling.
RIKER:
He...
Data, we don't know that
this can become alive.
It is very important
for me to know that, sir.
I never dreamed it was possible
that I might find some link
with a form like my own.
Understood.
We'll take it back
to the ship with us.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41242.45:
Despite having only a few hours
in which to explore
Data's home planet,
we have discovered something
which may explain
Data's beginnings
if we can properly assemble
and communicate
with what we've found.
Signal from the Captain.
They need you
at the debriefing.
I've been most anxious to hear
the chief engineer's opinion,
Mr. Argyle.
Do you believe
he can be made to function?
It appears to include
all the components
in your body.
Not that we fully
understand your
construction either.
We have our top specialists
working on its
construction, Mr. Data.
Just one thing.
Without disassembling
you, of course
if we should
need more...
If we should need
to compare this
with the way
you're put together...
Bringing it up here
was the right thing
to do, Number One.
We were just saying, Data,
that if your duplicate
functions,
it may answer
a lot of questions.
Does it appear
to have, uh...
all your parts?
Completely, sir.
LA FORGE:
Will...
will we know how
to turn it on?
PICARD:
All right.
Legitimate questions
about any of this
need not be asked
apologetically.
You feel uncomfortable
on aspects
of your duplicate, Data.
We feel uncomfortable, too,
and for no logical reason.
If it feels awkward
to be reminded
that Data is a machine,
just remember that we are merely
a different variety of machine.
In our case,
electro-chemical in nature.
Let's begin to handle this
as we would do anything else.
Agreed, Captain.
Let's begin with you, Data.
Well, sir,
a good starting point may be
why was I given human form?
Well, to make it
easier for humans
to relate to you--
had to be.
But your designer
may have had
something else
to prove as well.
That human-shaped robots
need not be clumsy or limited
in their performance.
You certainly operate
as well as we do, Data.
Better in some ways, sir.
RIKER:
You might want to have
a look at this, Captain.
It could be a link to the
disappearance of the colonists.
It was displayed in the lab--
no doubt by proud parents.
It could be just
a child's imagination
but several children
did similar drawings.
Dr. Crusher to the Captain.
At this point, sir,
we very much need
Mr. Data's help.
He's on his way, Doctor.
ARGYLE:
Is the electromagnetic
synthemometer reading
positive or negative?
WOMAN:
Positive.
Press your fingers there,
Doctor.
There.
It operates almost as a switch.
And these small projections?
An android
alarm clock.
Is that amusing?
They time how long
I remain unconscious.
Are you certain
about us using
these heating
devices, Data?
I will feel nothing at all.
Marvelous.
It should all be
a lot simpler
once we see how your
circuitry's connected.
I won't mention
it to anyone.
You have my word.
If you had
an off switch, Doctor,
would you not
keep it secret?
I guess I would.
Yes, notice the
microcircuitry here
and here...
and then another
fibroid-like
connection here.
Let's close up.
It seemed
to go well
thanks to a look
inside Mr. Data
but there have been no signs
of consciousness yet.
RIKER:
It certainly is
a good match for Data, sir.
PICARD:
Do you think so, really?
I wonder which of them
was made first.
He was.
But they found him
to be imperfect
and I was made to replace him.
You may call me Lore.
But I am also troubled by it
describing you as imperfect.
Human language gives me
difficulty, too, sir.
Imperfect could mean that I lack
certain abilities he possesses.
Hmm, I wonder.
But the point of this is
whether you and it
have approximately
the same
capabilities.
We do, sir,
and your referring to him
as "it"
suggests that I, too,
fit into the category
of a thing.
Oh, uh, I... I see your point.
My apologies.
Gladly accepted, sir.
As for Lore's abilities,
his use of syntax
and grammar suggests
he was given
human memories
similar to my own.
And you have about equal
physical strength
and mental
abilities?
I believe so, sir.
Which requires that I now
ask you a very serious question.
Since the two of you
are closely related
to each other...
The answer, sir,
is that my loyalty is to you
and Starfleet, completely.
Thank you, Commander.
I was certain of that.
LA FORGE:
And helm control is here
with the ship's heading
being given in measurements
we call degrees--
360 of them
in a full circle this way.
Then you say mark.
On the nose.
Which separates it from
another full 360-degree circle
this way on a right angle
to this one.
So, by ordering a heading
so many degrees this way
and so many this way
the ship can travel
in any direction--
all three dimensions.
And the square
of a hypotenuse
to the right triangle...?
Is equal to the sum of
the square of the other two...
two something--
which I
once heard
but never understood.
All of which you will
learn more about
when the Captain
has approved
your being on
the Bridge.
Have I committed
an offense?
You will find that there are
many rules on starships
that must be learned.
You're very clever, Wesley.
I now have duties
to perform, correct?
Were you ever
this anxious
to please, Data?
Never.
I judge Lore to be superior
in that desire.
Because I was designed
to be so human, my brother.
I enjoy
pleasing humans.
LA FORGE:
"My brother."
That has a nice sound
to it, Data.
You consider it important
to please humans?
It's not important?
There are many things
of importance.
Some more than others.
Do you realize
that Commander Riker's
hypotenuse question
tricked you
into showing
your knowledge
was greater than you
were indicating?
He didn't seem
that clever.
I'll be more careful.
You tend to underestimate
humans, my brother.
Praising young Wesley
on the helm, for example.
A child.
He has a child's body,
but we have found him
to be much more.
Thank you for that
information, too.
You do care
about how I perform.
I pledge to be worthy
of your teaching,
my brother.
Try not to be jealous
of my ability.
What information
are you requesting?
Everything available
on a Dr. Noonien Soong.
Ah, good old
"Often Wrong" Soong.
A joke, brother.
Actually, he was
a genius by human standards.
But he destroyed
his own reputation
by making what seemed
wild promises
about his positronic
brain design--
almost all of which failed.
Promises he later proved
to be true.
Which made you and
me possible, brother.
Our beloved father.
Will I soon have a uniform
like that, brother?
If you get one
the way I did, Lore,
it will mean four years
at the Academy
another three as Ensign,
ten or 12 on varied space duty
in the Lieutenant grades...
A system designed to compensate
for limited human ability
and you, brother, are beginning
to think as a human.
You and I
are completely
different
from them.
Are you truly satisfied
with the knowledge and memory
of a few hundred
human colonists?
Suppose it could reflect
thousands
or millions
or the knowledge
of hundreds of millions
of life-forms of every kind?
How?
We will discuss that in time.
And will we also
discuss, Lore,
which of us
was constructed first?
It would be foolish
to underestimate you, brother.
Yes, I lied when I said
you were made first,
but with good reason.
Dr. Soong made me perfect
in his first attempt,
but he made me
so completely human
the colonists became envious
of me.
You lived with the colonists?
Until they petitioned Soong
to make a more comfortable,
less perfect android.
In other words, you...
brother.
Haven't you noticed
how easily I handle
human speech?
I use their contractions.
For example,
I say "can't"
or "isn't"
and you say "cannot"
and "is not."
♪ I say tomato, and you ♪
♪ Say tomahto ♪
♪ I say potato
and you say potahto... ♪
A very old joke.
But then you also have trouble
with their humor.
Am I right?
Quite true.
I keep trying
to be more human
and keep failing.
Do you realize, brother,
I can help you
become more human?
And do you realize, Lore,
that I am obligated
to report all of this
to our ship's Captain?
I assumed as much when I began
studying you.
May I use this
to learn more
about this vessel
and its customs?
Use it also to describe
for the Captain
the time you spent
among the colonists
including everything
you know
about what happened
to them.
I promise a report
of great detail and accuracy.
Thank you, Lore.
I now have duties to perform.
Unless, of course,
you need something more.
I have more than I dreamed
possible, brother.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41242.5:
Thanks to Lore's report,
we now know what happened
to the colonists.
Beginning with
a child's drawing
enhanced by Lore's
description,
our computer has constructed
the image
of a great crystalline entity
which feeds on life,
insatiably ravenous
for the life force found
in living forms
capable of stripping all life
from an entire world.
But how did Data
escape that thing? Or Lore?
Lore had been disassembled.
He explained it as jealousy
from the colonists
and Data wasn't yet alive
at that time.
Which explains why Data
could be left outside
in no danger
from that creature.
Whatever happened
to the colonists,
he would be found
by the first
Starfleet crew
that responded to
the signal he transmitted.
By which Dr. Soong
left proof behind
that his experiment did work.
Captain...
how believable do you find
that crystal thing?
With so little of even
our galaxy explored,
I find it
at least possible.
Data, are you expecting Lore
to come up here?
He left your quarters
some time ago.
To go?
My turbo sensors say
he went to Deck Four. Worf?
Where he examined
some microminiature work tools
and some fine grind
quadratanium.
Which is used in
our construction.
That particular compound
is no more suspicious, sir,
than a human looking
for an antiseptic
or an ointment.
Nevertheless,
I should check it out.
You're watching
everything he does, Data?
Is that the act
of a brother?
It's the act
of a Starfleet officer
obeying his Captain, Doctor.
Captain, speaking strictly
as security chief,
how much can you trust Data now?
I trust him completely,
Lieutenant,
but everyone should also realize
that that was a necessary
and legitimate
security question.
Thank you, sir.
( door opens )
Lesson number one
in becoming more human:
You must observe
all human customs.
Champagne?
An ancient ritual
still practiced
when they observe
events of importance.
My brother, I toast
our discovery
of each other.
May it fill our lives
with new meaning.
I have some doubts
about the value
of human customs...
in this...
Brother...
And let us toast,
also, Dr. Soong
who gave me
the full richness
of human needs and ambitions.
A perfect match for my mind,
my body.
Brother... help me.
And let us toast also
the great crystal entity
with whom I learned
to communicate.
Before Dr. Soong disassembled me
I earned its gratitude
by revealing
the way to the colonists.
Can you imagine its gratitude
when I give it the life
on this vessel?
This is strange, sir.
I show Commander Data
transmitting on
a subspace channel.
I know Data's been doing
considerable research
into Dr. Soong's
background.
Let's be sure.
Wesley, would you look in
on Commander Data, discreetly?
Yes, sir.
Crystal entity
upon arriving here
you can identify me
as the machine named Data.
( door chime )
End of message.
Come in, please.
Glad you were here, Wesley.
Lore suddenly attacked me
and I had to turn him off.
Why did he do that, Data?
He discovered
we have been using sensors
to follow what he does.
I practiced his facial tic.
Do I have it right?
I'd suggest
you forget imitating him.
If you'd said
we've been
using the sensors
instead of we have
I might have suspected
you were Lore.
Yes, I do use language
more formally than Lore.
Please inform the Captain
I will come up on the Bridge
and report on this.
Aye, sir.
Wes, tell me again
how Data said he
immobilized Lore.
He told me he just
turned him off, Mom...
uh, Doctor.
Question, Mr. Data.
Did you or did you not
swear me to secrecy
about your off switch?
A change of
mind, Doctor.
If I cannot trust
the Bridge crew,
whom can I?
Captain, I'm picking up
a bogey coming in
on a five
o'clock tangent.
YAR:
It's transmitting no ID signal,
Captain.
RIKER:
Set main viewer on that tangent.
PICARD:
Shields up; go to yellow alert.
Transmit friendly
greetings--
all languages,
all frequencies.
I can't believe anything's
overtaking us this fast.
Beautiful, isn't it?
I recognize it, sir.
It's the crystal image
Lore described.
My God.
YAR:
Still no ID
being transmitted, sir.
Also no answer
to our inquiries.
Did you get
a direct look at it?
It's like a giant
snowflake crystal
but much
more complex.
The entire
electromagnetic spectrum
seems to play
about inside it,
but I haven't the slightest
idea what it is, sir.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Data, if there's anything else
that Lore could tell us about it
it may be
important.
Can you control him enough
to question him?
I will have to examine
him to know, sir.
Captain, recommend
that you do not let...
him roam
the ship freely.
Ensign.
Wesley is simply showing himself
to be alert and responsible,
something to be encouraged.
Come. You can watch
everything I do.
Not if I have a choice.
That is enough,
Ensign!
When addressing
a senior officer...
I've guided his training, sir.
I'm the one at fault.
You will show
the proper respect.
I will accompany you down there
to make certain of it.
With your approval,
of course, sir.
Careful of Lore.
Good, he is still unconscious.
Notice the same twitch
even though he is unconscious.
Stay back.
We may have problems if he
senses someone else is near.
Lore.
I have a few
questions to ask you.
Lore, it is Data.
He senses you.
I cannot control him
if you stay.
Please, I will record
everything he says.
And you bring it
to the Bridge immediately.
And you want to be
as stupid as them...
dear brother?
PICARD:
Well, Number One?
It was Lore, sir--
same facial twitches
that we've seen all along
lying unconscious on the floor
exactly as Data had described
and then it suddenly
became violent
apparently sensing
that Wesley and I were present.
Or is it Lore pretending
to be Data and faking it all?
I asked for Commander
Riker's report
acting Ensign Crusher
and since it now seems clear
that you are unable
to function
within the limits
of that appointment...
Captain.
Deflector shields holding, sir.
Bring photon torpedoes
to ready.
Main phasers to ready.
Go to red alert, please.
Weapons now readied, sir.
No, Captain,
let me talk to it.
You didn't say
you could do that.
Affirmative. Talk to it.
Open hailing frequencies.
Crystal form,
I identify myself as Data.
Advising you
to stop your attack.
The humans here are powerful--
capable of injuring
or even destroying you.
Now I call
that communicating.
Suggest moving fast to
confirm what I told it, sir.
Permission to use
the large transporter
in Cargo Room Three.
There I can beam up
some living pattern,
perhaps
a large tree.
Which you'll beam over
next to the entity.
That is
correct, Riker.
Our ship's phasers will then
blast and disintegrate it
proving we are dangerous.
Make it so.
Sir?
Do it.
Sir, I know
this may finish me
as acting Ensign...
Shut up, Wesley.
Lieutenant, pick
a good security team
and let me
know what he does.
Aye, sir.
"Shut up, Wesley"?
Doctor...
And since
I am finished here, sir
may I
point out...
Shut up, Wesley.
That everything that I have said
would've been listened to
if it came from
an adult officer.
Request permission
to return to my quarters, sir.
Agreed. Doctor, go with him.
You're putting me
off the Bridge?
I'm asking you to keep
an eye on your son
during all
of this, Doctor.
( alarm sounding )
Emergency close.
Now show me
your warrior fierceness.
I'll look.
But I shouldn't have let you
talk me into this.
Mom, it's Data!
He's been hurt.
It's Data, Mom.
I heard you know how
to turn them on.
This is very serious.
So just tell me
to "Shut up, Wesley"
and I will.
You're being
very unfair, Wes.
Data, the crystal thing
is outside
somewhere close to the ship
and Lore is loose
on the inside.
How badly are
you hurt, Data?
I will function sufficiently
to stop Lore, Doctor.
Crystal entity form,
it's your old friend.
Very good.
You've understood perfectly
so far.
Next I will signal
that I'm about to transport
something out
at which time
the deflector shields
will turn off for a moment
and if you move
in at that time
it...
How sad, dear brother.
You make me wish
I were an only child.
Then why this marvelous gift?
The troublesome
little man-child.
Are you prepared for the kind of
death you've earned, little man?
If you take one more step
towards my son...
Ah... motherhood.
Back off
or I'll turn
your little man
into a torch.
I promise him exquisite pain
unless you obey
me, too, brother.
Move away, Data.
Please.
Do you see now
the advantages
of being completely human?
It includes kindness.
I give you
your life, Doctor.
Go quickly
and I may not injure
your son at all.
I will stay with Wesley, Doctor.
Go!
Or he'll be
shrieking
by the count
of five.
One
two
three
four...
Thank you for my
human qualities, Dr. Soong.
Wait!
A small payment
for your son's misdeeds.
Wes, the transporter.
Wesley, now!
Lore's gone, sir. Permanently.
Doctor, now that Wesley's safe,
go to Sick Bay at once.
Captain, that crystal thing
has begun to move away.
Data, you all right?
Yes, sir, I'm fine.
Then get rid
of that damned twitch
and put on a correct uniform.
Yes, Captain.
Ensign Crusher,
you able to return to duty?
Yes, sir.
Then do so
and let the Bridge know
that all is well down here.
Aye, sir.
RIKER:
It's gone, sir.
Without Lore,
it had no way to reach us.
And we're overdue
for our computer refit.
Number One,
have you ever considered
whether Data is more human
or less human
than we want?
I only wish we were all
as well-balanced, sir.
Agreed.