Captain's Log,
Stardate 41636.9:
As feared, our examination
of the seven-year-overdue
Federation freighter, Odin
disabled by an asteroid
collision
revealed no life signs.
However, three escape pods
were missing
suggesting the possibility
of survivors.
Ready to begin orbit
of Angel One, Captain.
Make it so, Mr. La Forge.
What kind
of place is this, Data?
Angel One is a
class-M planet, sir
supporting carbon-based
flora and fauna.
Sparsely populated
with intelligent
life-forms.
It is similar
in technological
development
to mid-twentieth
century Earth.
Kind of like being
marooned at home.
Assuming any of the survivors
made it this far.
Admittedly, it is
the closest planet to the Odin.
To travel the distance we did
in two days at warp one
would have taken
the Odin escape
pod five months.
Five months, six days,
11 hours, two minutes...
Thank you, Data.
And 57 seconds.
Captain, we're receiving
an audio signal from Angel One.
Starfleet are adamant
that we maintain
excellent diplomatic relations
with this planet.
Mr. Data
is there
any other
pertinent information
before we reply?
Angel One has evolved
into a constitutional
oligarchy.
It is governed
by a parliamentary body
consisting of six
elected mistresses
and headed by a female
they refer to as
"The Elected One."
It sounds like my own planet.
Klingons appreciate
strong women.
How current is this
information, Mr. Data?
A Federation vessel
last visited this planet
62 years ago,
Captain.
Counselor, as this is
a female-dominated society
you might wish to make
the initial contact.
Thank you,
sir.
Open hailing
frequencies.
Hailing frequencies
open, sir.
This is Counselor Deanna Troi
from the USS Enterprise.
I am Beata, The Elected One.
How may we assist you,
Counselor?
The Federation has neglected
to visit your planet
for far too long.
With your permission
we would like to correct
that oversight.
We feel in no way neglected,
Counselor.
A diplomatic courtesy call
is neither expected
nor required.
We also come in search
of possible survivors
from one of our freighters.
A brief visit will be tolerated.
TASHA:
They've broken off
transmission.
Ever feel like you're
not really wanted?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Where are you
fellas off to?
Our ski instructor
has us scheduled
for the Denubian Alps, sir.
Well, save us
some deep powder.
No problem, sir.
The holodecks have all
you'd ever need.
The away team
is ready, sir.
Angel One's
strategic importance
in this quadrant
may become vital.
Starfleet's hope
is that one day
this world may become
part of the Federation.
We'll do our best
to make a good
impression, Captain.
Energize.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
Our away team
has beamed down
to an unusual
matriarchal society
where the female is as
aggressively dominant
as the male gender was on Earth
hundreds of years ago.
Here, the female is the hunter,
the soldier
larger and stronger
than the male...
an arrangement considered
most sensible and natural.
I am Beata
The Elected One
of Angel One.
Representatives
of the Starfleet Enterprise
do you wish to petition?
We do.
We have reason
to hope that
survivors
from a damaged
Federation freighter
may be marooned
on your planet.
We are seeking
to learn
if this
is so.
Even a world as remote
as Angel One
has heard of Starfleet.
Searching the galaxy
for survivors
seems a petty task
for one of their
mighty vessels.
We don't consider
even one survivor petty.
Is this man implying that
we put a lesser value on life
than you do?
Not at all.
Our discovery
of the freighter
was unexpected.
We have a duty
to investigate.
I see.
And if you find any survivors
what then?
We would take
them with us
and see that they
were reunited
with their families.
Are we to take
these strangers
at their word?
Good question.
What reason could
we possibly have
to deceive you?
Another good
question.
Are there survivors
from the freighter
Odin on your planet?
I'm not prepared
to answer--
yet.
See to their
comforts.
( whispers ):
What's going on?
You will remain
here until summoned.
Is this area secure?
Can we talk?
Yes, tricorder doesn't show
any listening devices
or anything else of
a threatening nature.
Good. Troi?
There was much fear
in that room.
Paranoia, I'd say.
But of what?
I cannot say.
But their fear was not focused.
I sensed they were all
not concerned
for the same reason.
Undoubtedly, there are survivors
from the Odin on this planet.
I agree.
Otherwise, why would they
be so circumspect?
As Mistress Beata
is so fond of saying--
good question.
What do we do if they deny
the existence of survivors?
Let's not look for problems.
I want all departments to
prepare for a warp six trip
into the neutral zone
as soon as the away team
completes its mission.
Trouble, Captain?
Insurance.
Romulan battle cruisers
have been detected
near one of our
border posts.
They've requested
our assistance as soon as...
Ah! Ah!
Report, Mr. Crusher.
We finished
our ski lesson, sir
and it kind
of just happened.
On the Enterprise,
Mr. Crusher
nothing
"just happens."
What is that smell?
WORF:
Hmm, yes.
Slightly reminiscent
of Night-Blooming
throgni, Captain.
From home.
Quite stimulating,
wouldn't you say?
No.
I don't smell
anything.
I'm a little
congested with snow.
Don't let this
"just happen" again
Mr. Crusher.
Yes, sir.
Hmm!
Interesting.
An alcohol-based
synthetic
artificially reproducing
a floral scent.
It's called
perfume, Data.
The purpose of which is...
Certain cultures consider
perfume an aphrodisiac.
I am unfamiliar
with that term.
An aphrodisiac
is something used
to stimulate or enhance
sexual pleasure.
How does stimulation
of the olfactory nerves
affect the enjoyment
of sex?
The Elected One
will see you now.
You claim you intend
to remove these survivors
from our world.
Are you prepared to give
your solemn word on that?
We are.
You should know that
the vote was not unanimous.
Some of those among us
are suspicious.
Yet, the majority feel
we have no choice
but to trust you.
We don't understand the source
of your misgivings, Mistress
but we appreciate
your faith in us.
Make certain that faith
is not misplaced.
There are four
survivors
from the ship you call Odin.
All male.
Their leader is a man
who calls himself Ramsey.
If you'll deliver
these men to us
we'll have them off
your planet immediately.
If they were mine to deliver
I would do it
without hesitation.
Unfortunately,
their hiding place
has long eluded us.
Hiding place?
Why are they
in hiding?
Because they're fugitives
on Angel One.
And the quicker we get
rid of them, the better.
When these men came to us
seven years ago
they accepted our hospitality
quickly enough
but they gradually became
restive.
Started making unreasonable
demands.
Went against the natural order.
Using the technology
of the Enterprise
we might be able
to find these men.
I assumed as much.
But be warned, Counselor.
These men are dangerous.
( coughing )
CRUSHER:
Sick Bay to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
Wesley and one of his friends
have contracted some form
of respiratory ailment.
A respiratory ailment?
Is it contained?
I hope so.
I've isolated the 12 students
who were on the Quazulu VIII
field trip.
How contagious is it?
Still running tests.
The key is to figure how
the virus is transmitted.
So far, I've been able
to rule out
person to person contact.
Well, keep with it, Doctor.
Starfleet has very important
business for us
as soon as
the away team returns.
I don't fancy the idea
of my crew being infected.
Data, what's the best way
to go about finding Ramsey
and the other survivors?
If we can isolate
something unique
to the Odin
survivors
perhaps an element
not otherwise found
on Angel One,
we can utilize
the Enterprise
scanners.
Mr. Data will need
access to your library.
Our library is far
too sophisticated
for a man
to comprehend.
I am an android,
Mistress
though anatomically,
I am a male.
An amusing notion.
Maybe you could
teach our males
a thing or two.
Trent, see to
the android's needs.
Bridge to
Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
The away team
requests
that we scan the
planet's surface
for traces
of platinum.
Have Mr. La Forge
break fixed orbit
and initiate a search pattern.
Aye, Captain.
Geordi.
Search pattern
initiated... now.
This was delivered
for you.
Good.
It's for my meeting
with Beata.
You're not going
to wear that.
Of course.
Part of this mission
is diplomatic.
I have requested an audience
with a head of state
and I will honor her by
wearing indigenous apparel.
I don't believe this.
You're going to put
that thing on
and parade around
like one of them?
Why, what is this attitude?
On Kabatris, I had to wear furs
to meet with
the leadership council
and on Armus IX
I wore feathers.
This objection doesn't
have anything to do
with the fact that Beata
is a woman
and an attractive one,
does it?
This is quite
unnecessary, Doctor.
I'm fine!
You're infected
with the virus, Captain.
In my opinion,
you are no longer
physically able
to effectively
command this vessel.
That is ridiculous,
Doctor!
I've an away team down there
in less than friendly territory
and, in addition,
I have an appointment
with several
Romulan battle cruisers...
You have
an appointment
in your cabin,
Captain
with your bed.
Is that an order, Doctor?
Yes.
I think I may sneeze.
A Klingon sneeze?
Only kind I know.
Lieutenant
La Forge
you have command
until further notice.
Please make the proper
ship's log entries.
Aye, sir.
Scanners indicate
a platinum trace.
Should I notify
the away team?
Make it so.
( whispers ):
Tasha.
What do you think?
( laughs )
Uh...
Well...
I got to say,
it's kind of sexy.
Thank you,
Lieutenant.
Actually, it feels
quite comfortable.
( giggles )
How handsome you look.
Thank you.
The Enterprise reports
a possible location
for Mr. Ramsey
and the other
survivors.
So soon?
I'm impressed.
I am suspicious.
You don't believe me?
Not yet.
I hear the words,
but not the sincerity.
You had your opportunity
to object, Ariel.
You were
in the minority.
ARIEL:
After seven years,
the great ship Enterprise
comes to repatriate
a small group
of insignificant people.
Mistress Ariel,
I hear the words
but not the sincerity.
You should listen
more carefully.
Excuse me, Mistress.
I have matters
to attend to elsewhere.
With your permission
we'd like to
begin our search
immediately.
By all means.
But I'm sure
Counselor Troi
and the others
can see to that
without you.
If I recall, you had
a gesture of goodwill
you wish to give to me.
Certainly
that can wait
until we've recovered
the survivors.
Are you suggesting that
the women in your party
are incapable
of accomplishing that task
without the help
of a man?
Not at all.
Lieutenant Yar
and Counselor Troi
are completely
qualified.
You're very generous
with your praise.
Inform them that you
will remain here with me.
Riker to Lieutenant Yar.
This is Yar.
In the interest
of diplomatic relations
I'll remain here
with Mistress Beata
while you conduct our search.
Commander?
You have your instructions.
Relax, we have
much to discuss.
Set phasers to stun.
I wish they
weren't necessary.
A justified precaution,
Counselor.
Mistress Beata observed
that Mr. Ramsey
and his men are dangerous.
Lieutenant Yar to Enterprise.
LA FORGE:
Go ahead, Tasha.
Three to beam to the location
of that platinum trace, Geordi.
Coordinates set.
Energize.
Tasha!
Welcome.
I've been expecting you.
Picard to Bridge.
( Klingon sneeze )
La Forge here.
Status report.
82 more reported cases
of the virus, sir.
Dr. Crusher has converted
the holodeck
into an isolation ward.
And the... the away team?
Well, no recent
contact, sir.
But I have informed them
of the medical situation up here
and of the growing
Romulan threat to our
neutral zone outpost.
Keep me advised.
You have the Bridge
until Commander Riker returns.
Engineering reports
a computer mal...
( Klingon sneeze )
I'm sorry.
I'm getting sick.
I'm sure half the ship
knows that by now.
Report to Sick Bay,
Lieutenant.
Engineering to Bridge.
( sighs )
La Forge here.
The computer won't accept
the varying climate controls.
On my way.
With all respect,
Lieutenant
there are people
to do that job now.
La Forge to Engineering.
Lieutenant Wong
knows that system.
I'm sure she'll be able
to resolve all problems.
Worf...
thanks for the advice.
( Klingon sneeze )
RAMSEY:
How did you find me?
DATA:
Actually, it was quite simple.
Angel One
has no platinum.
Enterprise scanners
did the rest.
Platinum, was it?
My wings.
I kept them for
their sentimental value.
Where are the other survivors,
Mr. Ramsey?
Oh, they're nearby.
They're packing,
as a matter of fact
since we can no longer
remain here.
Seven years on an alien planet
and I sense no anticipation,
no excitement at being rescued?
What is it that you think
that you're rescuing me from?
My shipmates and I
have all taken wives.
A few even
have children.
You can't rescue a man from a
place that he calls his home.
Why were you so hesitant
at first
to tell us
about the Odin survivors?
Because Ramsey and his
men are anarchists.
I had to make sure
you weren't here
to fuel their struggle.
I like the way
your eyes pick up
the color
of your tunic.
It's not our position
to interfere
in the domestic affairs
of other societies.
But you can
interact?
Of course.
Otherwise,
how can we learn?
Is that why you're
here with me tonight?
To learn?
Yes.
About our society?
Well, in our society
it is the men who are
the fortunate ones
enjoying all
life has to offer
while we women
devote ourselves
to the obligation
of making life work.
In our society we share
the responsibilities
and the pleasures
equally.
Which is why I'm able
to be here with you
while the women of the away team
go to find Ramsey.
You have to remind
me to thank them
when they come back
for giving us
this time.
You resist.
Don't you find
me attractive?
Yes, I find you
very attractive.
You attract me
like no man ever has.
It's not my function
to seduce or be seduced
by the leader
of another world.
That's not
the reason.
No, it's not.
But will you still
respect me in the morning?
I hope so.
Thank you, Trent.
You may go.
Compliments
of the USS Enterprise.
It's called an Albeni
meditation crystal.
Very impressive.
And now, I must
repay you in kind.
Five months in a rescue pod
no bigger than this room
is an eternity I hope none
of you will ever have to face.
When we finally
made it here
we thought we'd died
and gone to heaven.
You've seen the women
on this planet.
They're tall and strong
and very lovely.
But after the newness wore off
we started to see
how the men were treated.
There's no votes,
there's no opinions
there's no respect.
None of which
is your concern
any longer, Mr. Ramsey.
Call the others in,
please.
It's time
to leave.
Despite their
problems, Lieutenant
we happen to like it
here on Angel One.
We're not
going anywhere.
But Mistress Beata...
Mistress Beata be damned!
Her wish is not my command,
and neither is yours.
You can't force us to go.
DATA:
Mr. Ramsey
is correct, Counselor.
The Odin was not a starship,
which means her crew
is not bound
by the prime directive.
If he and the others
wish to stay here
there is absolutely
nothing we can do about it.
( coughing )
LA FORGE:
Bridge to Sick Bay.
How are you doing, Doctor?
We have more sick
than we do beds.
So far, I've been forced
to confine over 300
to their private quarters.
We're going to be
seriously undermanned
if we're forced to engage
the Romulans in battle.
The Romulans are your problem,
Lieutenant--
trying to find an inoculant
is mine.
This virus mutates
every 20 minutes.
But we haven't
had any fatalities... yet.
If this continues, there will be
no one left to run the ship.
If this continues,
Lieutenant La Forge
nobody will be healthy enough
to care.
Yar to Enterprise.
Enterprise here, go ahead.
Prepare to beam three to our
previous location, Geordi.
After regrouping
with Commander Riker
we'll return
to the ship.
I suggest you make that
on the double, Tasha.
We have a real medical emergency
brewing up here.
One-third of the crew is down
and the latest information
from the neutral zone outpost
is that more Romulan vessels are
converging on that area.
YAR:
I'll inform
the Commander.
Yar out.
One thing before we go.
You said you were
expecting us.
Why?
I can't answer that.
We wish you well,
Mr. Ramsey.
Energize.
They're gone.
BEATA:
What a refreshing
change--
to be with a man
who knows what he wants.
RIKER:
And doesn't have
to be told by a woman?
Exactly.
I knew you were bright
enough to understand.
See, women, by our very nature
want only what is best
for their men.
Men are not objects
to be possessed, Mistress Beata.
Of course
they're not.
It was merely
a figure of speech.
( doorbell rings )
Enter.
What is so important
you find it necessary
to intrude upon my privacy?
They have returned, Mistress
but without Ramsey
or the others.
Your advanced technology
has proven inadequate?
What happened, Tasha?
Mr. Ramsey and the other
survivors refuse to leave.
You gave me
your solemn word.
I'm sorry, there's
nothing else we can do.
I'm sorry as well.
Since you refuse
to take them with you
I am left with no choice
but to sentence them all
to death.
Come.
It looks horrible
tastes worse
but it's absolutely
guaranteed
to make you
feel better.
I knew you'd like it.
Are you wearing cologne?
Like something
I smelled earlier
something Klingon.
Lieutenant Worf and I
detected the same scent
when we bumped
into your son
at the holodeck.
It's that smell.
That's how
the virus travels.
An airborne particle
whose sweet scent
inspires deep inhalation.
And once inside the body
becomes that damn virus!
I have work to do.
You're excused, Doctor.
What's the latest
on the Enterprise's
medical situation?
Dr. Crusher
feels the virus
will undoubtedly
run unchecked
through
the entire ship.
Attempts to develop
an inoculant
have so far ended
in failure.
Lieutenant La Forge
still has Bridge command
pending your return, sir.
And what about the Romulans
entering the neutral zone?
The border outpost
reports a contingent
of seven Romulan
battle cruisers
within sensor range.
The USS Berlin has answered
the distress call.
However, should
hostilities erupt
both the outpost
and the starship
will be outgunned.
It is felt that the
Enterprise's presence
in the area will be
a vital show of force.
Some show
of force.
The Enterprise
could fly on autopilot
but with that virus
knocking down our crew
we're going to be
in sorry shape
if things turn ugly.
I think it's time
we leave this place.
It doesn't feel right to leave
while Beata is determined
to execute those people.
She has to find
them first.
Ramsey and his bunch
have been fugitives
for years.
I suspect he's pretty good
at evading capture.
Something's wrong.
Before you go back
to your ship
there's something
I want you to see.
We were no harm to anyone.
Why did you tell them
where to find us?
You brought this upon yourself.
You and the traitor.
One does not need the technology
of the Enterprise
to follow
Mistress Ariel
sneaking out
to warn her husband.
Let her stand with him now!
For tomorrow
they will die together.
You claim to be
an advanced society
and yet you resort
to executions
in order to suppress those
who don't share your views.
I don't expect you
to understand.
Why? Because I'm
only a man?
You'll accomplish nothing
with that attitude.
Mistress Beata
if you had an alternative
to the execution of Ramsey
and his followers,
would you take it?
Is that not the way
of an advanced society?
Then let us meet with the men
from the Odin one last time.
Let me try to convince them
to leave here with us.
Will you also include those
from this world
who unwisely choose
to follow Ramsey and his group?
Yes. All of them.
( murmuring )
Mistress Beata is willing
to give you a second chance.
We're prepared to take
your entire group with us.
That's very kind
of you.
But we're not going.
Haven't you been
paying attention, Ramsey?
You're scheduled
to be executed tomorrow.
We don't want to die.
We don't want to leave, either.
There's no time to debate
the issues.
You're going with us
whether you choose
to go or not.
DATA:
Excuse me,
Commander
but removing any of these people
against their will
would be a violation of several
Starfleet regulations
not the least of which
would be the prime directive.
I realize
that, Mr. Data.
I'd rather face
a court-martial
than live
with the guilt
of leaving these people
to their death.
Commander Riker
to the Enterprise.
This is the Enterprise,
Crusher here.
It must be worse up
there than we thought.
Doctor, where is
Lieutenant La Forge?
He's right here,
but he's in bad shape.
Notify the transporter room
I have 14 to beam up.
I can't allow it.
This virus is totally
out of control here.
Doctor, these people are
facing their death down here.
They might be facing
the same thing up here.
Until I have a better idea
what I'm dealing with
no one can beam up.
I'm sorry, Will,
but you must wait.
Understood.
Doctor, would this virus
have any effect on Mr. Data?
Not likely.
You're going
back there alone.
I want you to get
the Enterprise
into the neutral zone
before it's too late.
This is Data standing by
to beam up.
What of them?
I don't know, Deanna.
Mistress Beata
invites you to witness
this morning's
reaffirmation
of Angel One's
moral imperative.
Is that the civilized word
for murder on this world?
You send Mistress Beata
our regrets.
The Elected One
will not look fondly...
DATA:
Enterprise to Commander Riker.
They're still here.
Riker here.
Data, I gave you
direct orders
to get to the neutral
zone immediately.
Explain the delay.
To be precise, Commander
you ordered me to reach
the neutral zone
before it is too late.
After relieving
Lieutenant La Forge
I computed the length of time
the border outpost
and the USS Berlin
can safely withstand
a Romulan attack--
deducted our time to destination
at maximum warp speed.
That leaves Dr. Crusher
48 minutes
to develop an inoculant
to the virus.
Which means there's
still time
for us to do something.
48 minutes.
Ah, 47, sir.
Perhaps, Data, perhaps.
Thank you
for following my orders
so precisely, Data.
On second thought, Trent,
we would be honored
to witness your moral
imperative in action.
We have determined that
the heretical teachings
of Ramsey and his followers
are inconsistent
with harmonious
life on Angel One.
Our patient efforts
to silence revolutionary
voices have failed.
Therefore, we are
left with none
but the most final
alternative.
( sizzling sound )
BEATA:
As you can see
we are not
without compassion.
Your deaths
will be
swift and painless.
Mistress Beata
before we see
living examples
of your compassion,
may I speak?
Is this a plea
for leniency?
Nothing of the sort.
As the governing body
of Angel One
you're entitled
to execute your laws
or your citizens
as you see fit.
Make your point
so we can proceed
with this
unpleasant business.
When you spoke
of the prisoners
you used the term
revolutionary.
Indeed, death has been
known to stop revolutions.
But I suspect it's
not a revolution
that Angel One
is hoping to stop.
It's evolution.
Mr. Ramsey and
the Odin survivors
did not initiate
the waves of dissent
that are rippling
through your planet.
Their presence here
merely reinforced
the change in attitudes
between men and women
that was already
well underway.
They became symbols
around whom others
who shared their views
could gather.
You may eliminate
the symbols
but that does not mean
death to the issues
which those symbols
represent.
No power in the universe
can hope to stop
the force of evolution.
Be warned.
The execution of Mr. Ramsey
and his followers
may elevate them
to the status of martyrs.
Martyrs cannot be silenced.
Beata!
Stop.
We will adjourn
to consider your words.
Thank you.
I don't know
if it was enough.
Sick Bay to Bridge.
Go ahead, Doctor.
Bingo, Data.
Bingo?
I fail to see
the relevance, Doctor.
Is that not a reference
to an ancient Earth game?
It's also a reference
to success, Data.
I've got the inoculant.
Excellent, Doctor.
We still have 17 minutes left.
I will inform
the away team immediately.
Enterprise to Riker.
We are now ready to have you
beamed up, Commander.
Data, Ramsey
and the prisoners
are with us
in the Great Hall.
I want you to lock
in the transporter.
Prepare to evacuate
the entire group
but for now, stand by.
Understood, Commander.
After careful consideration,
this legislature has voted
to stay the execution
of the prisoners.
Their children will be
returned to them immediately.
Do not rejoice
prematurely.
Ramsey and his followers
are to be exiled
to a distant and
unpopulated region.
Life will be
difficult there
with little time
left for revolutionary...
or evolutionary upheaval.
As some have
observed
we may not be able
to stop evolution
but perhaps we can reduce it
to a slow crawl.
For a man, you can be
very clever, Commander Riker.
Riker to Enterprise.
Belay my previous
order, Mr. Data.
There will now be
only three to beam up.
Energize.
Welcome home.
It's good to be back.
Are they recovering?
Slowly, but yes.
And the Captain?
( hoarsely ):
The Captain is fine, thank you.
PICARD:
Mr. Data has
been briefing me
on the away team's
comportment, Number One.
TROI:
We, uh...
improvised, sir.
Mmm... I look forward
to your reports.
Don't we have a call to pay
on the Romulans, Captain?
Indeed, we do.
Mr. Data, set course
for the neutral zone.
Warp six.
Coordinates set,
warp six.
On your mark,
sir.
( barely audible )
Engage.
Sir?