Captain's Log,
Stardate 41365.9:
The Enterprise has
been ordered to Starbase 74
in orbit around Tarsas III.
A routine maintenance check
of all systems will be made
and certain upgrades completed
including the holodeck,
with which we've had problems.
I anticipate a glowing report.
This ship has performed
magnificently--
beyond anyone's expectations.
Coming into position.
Stand by to dock.
Ready to dock, sir.
Engage mooring beams,
and lock off.
Aye, sir.
And... docking complete.
Thank you, Number One.
Well done.
And...
well done, all.
COMPUTER:
Starbase Maintenance
approaching airlock five.
Commander Quinteros.
Request permission
to come aboard.
Granted. Welcome.
Captain.
Commander Riker.
Commander.
You're late.
We expected you a week ago.
We were unexpectedly delayed
at Omicron Pascal.
Ah. Is there anything specific
you wish to report
or that we should
be aware of?
No, we're very pleased
with the operation
of the Enterprise.
I knew you would be.
I was in charge of the team
which put it together.
Are these gentlemen the Bynars?
They're not gentlemen--
or ladies, Commander.
They're a unified pair.
They're always together.
This is One Zero
and this is Zero One.
They just finished upgrading
the computers on the Wellington.
Did a great job.
Your reputation
precedes you.
I'm very pleased you're going
to be improving our system.
It is a great pleasure
to work on such a large
mobile computer.
You have 48 hours,
because in 48 plus six
we have an appointment on
Pelleus V we must keep.
I thought we'd
have more time.
I'm sorry. This mission
can't be delayed.
If you want to
postpone the work...
Oh, no, this is
the best time
to do it.
We can complete
our work within
the time allotted.
They work very quickly,
but it'll be very tight.
Commander Riker and I
will stay on board
be available
should you need us.
Thank you, Captain.
I don't think
we'll need you until we're ready
for inspection.
The Bynars seem
perfect for this
even though
this is the first time
that I've ever
come in contact with them.
As I understand it,
over time
they have become
so interconnected
with the master computer
on their planet
that their language,
their thought patterns
have become as close
to binary as is possible
for organic beings.
It will be interesting
to see how they improve
a computer as advanced as ours.
Mm-hmm.
Bridge. Well, I have
a little work to finish up
then I'm going
to my cabin
I'm going
to put my feet up
I'm going to turn on
my personal relaxation light
and I'm going to lose myself
in the pages of some old novel.
What about you, Number One?
You've earned a rest.
I've never been very good
at organizing my time off.
Something'll turn up.
It always does.
( rapid binary chattering )
I'll be in my ready room.
And Number One...
good work.
I thought there were
only going to be two of you.
Because of the limited time
allotted us
we need others.
Is there a problem?
Uh, no.
No. No problem.
Then why are you
acting so excited?
Because we, uh, have to...
we are... stacking
to reconfigure
the computer
to communicate
with itself
more efficiently
and at higher speeds.
You act like you
don't believe them.
I'm not sure that I do.
Maybe it's nothing.
Perhaps it's just the way
another species behaves.
Maybe.
I'm going to stroll
around the ship.
You've got the Bridge.
Keep your eye on them.
Yes, sir.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
We've been challenged
to a friendly game
of parrises squares
by some of the
maintenance personnel.
Want to join us
on the starbase?
You've already got all
the players you need.
Oh, we can switch off.
No, you know, if you do
that in parrises squares
you lose the
rhythm of the game.
I can't talk you into
coming with us?
No, but win, all right?
The pride of the Enterprise
goes with you.
Rest assured, Commander
we will be victorious,
at whatever the cost.
Worf, it's just a game.
A friendly little
competition.
You work up a sweat,
you have a few laughs
and you make
new friends.
If winning is not important,
then, Commander, why keep score?
I think
he's pulling your leg.
Believe it or not
Worf is developing
a sense of humor.
I hope so,
for their sake.
Good luck.
( machinery winding down )
Computer, there's a power
reduction in section L-94.
Explain.
COMPUTER:
Unoccupied sections
are being closed down
in order to clear space
in the main computer banks.
It is necessary to facilitate
the system upgrade.
Full power can be restored
if needed.
LA FORGE:
Well, what do you think?
RIKER:
Tell me what
it's supposed to be
and then I'll give you
my opinion.
It is an attempt
at pure creativity.
What we're investigating is,
can Data be creative?
And this is my attempt,
with guidance from Geordi.
I suggested the zylo eggs.
Is that what those are?
Keep notes.
This project may turn out to be
of interest to scholars
in the future.
LA FORGE:
Really?
Well, of course.
Think about it.
A blind man teaching
an android how to paint?
That's got to be worth
a couple of pages
in somebody's book.
You look like you're packing
to leave forever.
Oh, Commander Riker.
No, I'm just
gathering my notes.
Professor Terence Epstein is
at this starbase.
Is that someone
I should know of?
He's the leading mind
in cybernetics.
He lectured
at my medical school.
You know the disaster
at Micromius? Well...
since then, I've been working
on an approach
that combines cybernetics
and regeneration.
It sounds impossible,
I know
but I have found an approach
that will work.
I mean, what an opportunity!
To have a chance
to talk with Dr. Epstein.
Sorry, Will.
I'd love to chat
but I have to go.
How's it going?
We are almost done.
The deviation
caused by a previous
probe has been corrected.
You may use the equipment
anytime you wish.
How much has been changed?
What exactly did you do?
Enhancement.
Nothing more.
( rapid binary chattering )
Would you like to try
the enhancement?
All right.
What should I choose?
Computer, I'd like someplace
to play some music--
a little atmosphere.
COMPUTER:
Specify.
Jazz.
COMPUTER:
Era?
Circa 1958.
COMPUTER:
Location?
Kansas City.
No, New Orleans.
Bourbon Street bar,
New Orleans.
Around 2:00 a.m.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
Enter when ready.
Very good.
Very good,
indeed.
Now I'll need someone
to play with.
A trio--
piano, bass, and drums,
and a 'bone for me.
Now an audience.
Whoa. Too many.
I was thinking of something
a little more intimate.
Great job, boys.
But, computer
blondes and jazz
seldom go together.
Now that is truly exceptional.
But more sultry.
Gentlemen, if this is
what you call enhancement
you've got a gift
for understatement.
( playing mellow jazz )
What's your name?
Tell me
you love jazz.
My name is Minuet
and I love all jazz
except Dixieland.
Why not
Dixieland?
You can't dance to it.
My girl.
What's a knockout
like you doing
in a computer-generated
gin joint like this?
Waiting for you.
Waiting for me?
You can't be serious.
Oh, yes, Will.
I've never been
more serious in my life.
( rapid binary chattering )
Can I ask you
a question about the Bynars?
Why not just ask them?
What is that high-pitched
sound you make?
That is our
primary language.
How can you can process
information at that speed?
We store information
with these buffers.
We receive information
all the time
and save it
until we need it.
How did you happen
to develop this ability?
It happened over
a long period of time.
To have a society
so intermixed with computers
it has tremendous advantages.
And a few
disadvantages.
Everything under control,
Ensign Crusher?
Fine, sir.
I was just trying
to find something out
about the Bynars.
Where's Commander Riker?
He's in holodeck four, sir.
Shall I call him
for you?
No, I'll go down
there myself.
Keep me apprised.
Yes, sir.
( playing mellow jazz )
Hey, man, the
chick digs you.
What makes
you say that?
Hey, look at her.
Maybe it's my music.
Yeah, well, about that--
don't give up your day job.
Too real.
You got that straight, slim.
Too real is too right.
Thanks for letting me
sit in.
Ain't nothing to it.
I'm going to have to leave
for awhile to see to my duties.
Your work's
very important to you.
It is me.
It's what I am.
Can we dance once
before you leave?
Sure, why not?
How did you learn
to dance so well?
From following you.
I can anticipate your lead.
So tell me about your work.
What is it about it that
consumes and enthralls you?
What an interesting
choice of words.
That's exactly
what it does.
You're very fortunate.
I know that.
To be exactly where
you want to be.
And it's great
that you realize it.
I'd be a fool not
to realize how lucky I am.
To be on this ship,
serving with these people--
it's like a dream come true.
Just like this.
A dream?
Is that what this is?
Is that what I am?
I know you're a
computer-generated image, but...
your smell...
your touch...
the way you feel...
even the things
you say and think seem so real.
Thank you.
How far can
this relationship go?
I mean, how real are you?
As real as
you need me to be.
( door opening )
Astounding.
Captain!
Oh, I'm sorry, Number One.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
No, it's all right.
Come on in.
You picked a wonderful locale.
This is something
I might have chosen myself.
Aren't you going
to introduce me?
Yes, of course.
Captain Picard,
this is Minuet.
Minuet, Captain
Jean-Luc Picard.
Enchantée.
Comme c'est merveilleux
de vous voir ici.
Incroyable!
Vous êtes Parisienne?
Au fond, c'est vrai.
Nous sommes tous Parisiens.
Oui, au fond, nous sommes
tous Parisiens.
The spirit of that city
can always enchant my soul.
I have been hoping
to meet you.
Oh, have I been the subject
of conversation?
Indirectly.
Come, join us, Jean-Luc.
A glass of wine?
Thank you.
Will was saying how much
he enjoys this assignment.
It's a credit to you.
For a ship and crew
to function well
it always starts
with the captain.
You set the tone.
At this moment, it is you
who are setting the tone.
The sophistication
of this program is remarkable.
In what way?
The holodeck has given us
woodlands and ski slopes
figures that fight
and fictional characters
with whom we can interact.
But you...
you're very different.
You adapt.
You spoke to me
in French.
It was very simple.
When I heard your name
I merely accessed
the foreign language bank.
That's very impressive.
Oui, mon chou.
Now what are
you doing?
I am awaiting inspiration.
WESLEY:
Commander Data?
This is Commander Data.
Go ahead, please.
I'm getting an indication
of possible trouble
in Main Engineering, sir.
Can you be
more specific?
I'm afraid not.
I'm reading a problem with
the magnetic containment field
which contains the antimatter.
Could you come up here?
We'll go to Engineering, since
that's where the trouble is.
Wes, don't disturb the Captain
or Commander Riker
until we check this out.
Aye, sir.
( computer beeping )
Bridge, this is
Main Engineering.
WESLEY:
This is the Bridge.
Are you running
any test programs up there?
No.
Are the Bynars?
Not to my knowledge.
Is there a problem?
I don't know.
There's no one on duty here
and we're getting
some very strange readings
from the magnetic
containment field.
The field is
deteriorating.
Contact the Captain
immediately.
I am initiating red alert.
( alarm sounding )
Data, I can't maintain
the integrity
of the containment
field.
Engineering to Captain.
If the antimatter
is released
the ship will be destroyed.
Nothing I do
has any effect.
I'm losing it.
Data, I've rechecked
every circuit.
This is not a misread
by the computer.
Computer,
situation analysis.
COMPUTER:
Estimate release of antimatter
in four minutes, 18 seconds.
17 seconds.
16 seconds.
Engineering to Bridge.
This is the Bridge.
DATA:
Alert starbase.
Inform them we are
abandoning the ship.
Tell them why.
Initiate automated
sequence for departure.
Set course and speed
to put maximum distance
between the Enterprise
and any inhabited planets.
Shouldn't we wait
for the Captain's approval?
DATA:
There is no time.
Based on all information
presently available
the decision is correct.
This is Lieutenant Commander
Data speaking for the Captain.
Abandon ship.
This is not a drill.
All personnel,
this is not a drill.
I say again
abandon ship.
All personnel,
this is not a drill.
Abandon ship.
COMPUTER:
Decks two through four
to cargo transporters.
Decks five through ten
proceed to transporters
one, two, three and four.
Decks six through 16
proceed to transporters
five, six
seven, eight, nine and ten.
CREWMAN:
Hold your positions,
please.
Prepare to energize.
And energize.
COMPUTER:
...proceed to transporters
11, 12, 13 and 14.
Decks 29 through 42
proceed to transporters 15, 16
17, 18, 19 and 20.
This is not a drill.
CREWMAN:
Well, key it up again.
What's going on?
Please, stand
out of the way.
The Enterprise is
being evacuated.
Why?
Some problem
in Engineering.
Get a security team
together.
Aye, Lieutenant.
Ship's Log, supplemental:
This is Lieutenant
Commander Data.
I have put the ship
on automated departure
and ordered the complete
evacuation of the Enterprise.
Everyone remaining is
leaving on foot or beaming off.
Computer, where are the
Captain and Commander Riker?
COMPUTER:
All decks empty.
Curious.
The captain is usually
the last to leave.
Let's go.
We've only got
41 seconds.
I think we're the last.
I hope we are.
Did you see the Captain
and Commander Riker?
No. Are they not
here on Starbase?
YAR:
No. We thought that--
You mean they're still
on board the Enterprise?
Yes. Sir, where is
your transporter room?
We have to beam
back and get them.
You haven't time.
CREWMAN:
This is Starbase 74.
The Enterprise magnetic field
is regenerating.
Wait a minute.
How is that possible?
CREWMAN:
Unknown.
YAR:
That changes
nothing.
The Captain and Commander Riker
must be in trouble
or they'd be here.
Now, look-- your ship
is almost clear.
( red alert sounding )
And the boy
never found out?
Oh, yes, but not
until later
when he came back into the
room with his little sister.
Oh, I bet both of them
were all smiles.
Yes, but by that time, both
of them had been found out.
You handled that
in a very thoughtful way.
You're very good
with people.
Don't you agree, Jean-Luc?
She's so very different
from the other images
we've experienced
on the holodeck, isn't she?
She's... she's
more intuitive.
It's as though she'd been
plugged into my subconscious.
She already knows
what I want her to say
before I'm aware of it myself.
PICARD:
I suppose it's an
understandable progression.
Computers make decisions
based on input
and we humans give off
a multitude
of subtle signs that...
that communicate
our emotions.
It's uncanny.
I could develop
feelings for Minuet
exactly as I would
for any woman.
Doesn't love always
begin that way--
with the illusion
more real than the woman?
Oh, Jean-Luc, spoken
like a true Frenchman.
Well, I think I'll be leaving.
Oh! Don't go.
Two's company.
We have time.
There's no rush.
I'd really like it
if you would stay.
Yes, Captain, stay.
This is your diversion,
Number One, not mine.
Wait. We haven't danced.
I... I don't dance.
Then some more wine.
No, thank you.
Wait!
Please!
Please, don't go.
You can't. Not yet.
Why? What's the matter?
Why can't he leave?
Exit.
( red alert sounding )
Captain to Bridge.
Situation report.
Riker to Bridge.
Computer, explain red alert.
COMPUTER:
Initiated as
a programmed response.
The magnetic field containing
the antimatter had weakened.
There was no
fail-safe available.
Why wasn't I notified?
COMPUTER:
Unknown.
Present condition?
COMPUTER:
The magnetic field
is now restored.
Containment is restored.
Propulsion is
at maximum efficiency.
Locate Lieutenant
Commander Data.
COMPUTER:
Not on board the Enterprise.
Explain.
COMPUTER:
All Enterprise personnel
except the Captain and First
Officer have been evacuated.
Evacuated?
Was the situation
that critical?
COMPUTER:
Yes.
Are we still docked
at the starbase?
No.
Position report.
Coordinates 4159.26
by 81921 by 312.
Heading, 233 mark 45.
Destination?
Planet Bynaus
in the Beta Magellan system.
The Bynars.
Am I to understand
the Bynars
have stolen
the Enterprise?
That information
is not available.
It's the Bynars,
and you're part of this.
Yes.
They made you the lure
to keep me here.
They programmed you
while I was relaxing.
Yes. When they saw
your interest in me
they thought I could distract
you and keep you here.
That explains Riker.
What about me?
Your being here was just
a fortunate happenstance.
What do they want with me?
What do they want
with the Enterprise?
What's their purpose?
I'm not programmed
to give you that information.
Come on, Number One.
We've got to regain control
of our ship.
Okay, so what
do we do?
Which is the nearest
Starfleet vessel?
The Trieste.
DATA:
I know the Trieste--
too small, too slow.
Plus it's 66 hours away.
Where are the Bynars?
I haven't seen them.
Then they are obviously
still aboard.
Another Starfleet vessel
must be sent
to intercept the Enterprise
at Bynaus.
They might be taking the ship
to their home planet.
What makes you think so?
It is the best place
for us to start.
Picard. Access.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
We know who has commandeered
the Enterprise-- the Bynars.
We can't communicate
with the Bridge.
Commander Riker and I
will now try to regain control
of our ship.
This way.
That's towards
Engineering.
That's our first step:
Verify containment
and initiate auto-destruct.
Initiate auto-destruct?
Our ship has been commandeered
by a force
of unknown size and intent.
We're here alone.
We must assume
the worst.
If we don't
regain control
then no one else
must have it, either.
Now...
this is the one decision
involving the operation
of this vessel
which requires you and I
to be in total agreement.
It's the time allotted
that concerns me.
As to that,
there's no option.
I know. It's a five-
minute countdown.
Well, that's sufficient
to get to the Bridge.
Once there, either we'll
get control of the vessel
shut off the auto-destruct
or we won't.
But this vessel must not
fall into hostile hands.
Then let's set it and get going.
COMPUTER:
Recognize Picard,
Jean-Luc, Captain.
Recognize Riker,
William T., Commander.
Set auto-destruct sequence.
COMPUTER:
Does the First Officer concur?
Yes, set auto-destruct
sequence... now.
COMPUTER:
Auto-destruct will detonate
in four minutes and 59 seconds.
The only place we can stop this
is on the Bridge. Let's go.
What do you make of this, sir?
PICARD:
An enormous
amount of data
is being received
and stored
in the main
computer.
Just stored. Why?
That's another piece
of this puzzle.
COMPUTER:
Bridge access denied.
They've locked it off.
We must find another
way to get in.
One of us could beam
into the Bridge.
No. It takes several
seconds to materialize.
You wouldn't
stand a chance.
I could beam
into the turbolift
force the doors,
take them by surprise.
No. We'll both beam
in simultaneously
to different areas
of the Bridge.
With luck, one of us
will be a distraction.
There must be only
four minutes left.
Still no response
from the Enterprise.
They would answer
if they could.
Someone else has
control of the ship.
Do you think
I am responsible?
Responsible?
How could you
possibly have known?
My station is
on the Bridge.
You can't be on the Bridge
every second, Data.
You are wrong, Geordi.
I can.
I do not need rest or diversion.
I should not have been painting.
I was negligent.
YAR:
That's a pointless
discussion, Data.
You could have been
on the Bridge
and it still
might have happened.
Commander Quinteros, you
have three ships in here.
We need one of them now.
We're rushing repairs
on the USS Melbourne
but it's still 18 hours
until she'll be ready.
There's nothing else you can do.
Set coordinates
for main Bridge.
Port forward for me,
aft for you.
You're on pad two.
I've set a ten-second delay.
Set phasers on stun.
Number One, good luck.
Over here, Captain.
Why did you steal my ship?
Please...
try... to...
help... us.
Cancel auto-destruct.
COMPUTER:
Does the First Officer agree?
Affirmative.
COMPUTER:
Auto-destruct, cancel.
We're in orbit
around Bynaus.
How are they?
They appear dead.
Let's see if we can get
some answers from Bynaus.
Their main computer is off.
All sensors reveal
that all the equipment
on their planet is inert.
They can neither send
nor receive any messages.
What about all those people
down there
who are totally dependent
on their computer?
Are they still
functioning?
They're probably
like these Bynars here, dying.
What is this all about?
Why did they steal the ship
and bring it here?
What is their purpose?
They went to an awful
lot of trouble
to clear computer space.
Let's see what they stored.
Captain, it's enormous.
Every byte of free space
in the computer
has been filled.
They must have
made a core dump
from their world
into our computer.
( warning beep )
I can't get in.
I wish they'd left a note.
Maybe they did.
Minuet.
Tell me what
this is all about.
A star in the Bynar system
went supernova
and they miscalculated.
The electrical magnetic pulse
from the explosion
was going to knock out
their main computer.
And so their only choice
was to transfer
all the stored information
and shut down until
after it passed
and then reactivate
their system
and transfer the information
back to the main computer.
The Enterprise has
the only mobile computer
large enough to handle
all that information.
So what went wrong?
Why are they dying?
The star went supernova
before it was expected
and you were late arriving
at Starbase 74.
Why didn't they
say something?
just ask for help?
I don't know.
I don't have
those answers.
Is there anything
we can do?
Yes, return the data
stored on the
Enterprise's computer
back to the one on Bynaus.
How can we do that?
You don't know?
Yes, if I had the file name.
But we don't. Do you?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
They wouldn't
intentionally hide it,
make it difficult
for us to find.
It must be right
in front of our faces.
We should contact
Starbase 74
and see if anyone
can decipher this.
They're dying.
They meant you no harm.
It was their world
they were trying to save.
Help them, Will. Hurry.
Please.
Starbase 74, this
is the Enterprise.
Do you read me?
This is Starbase 74.
Captain Picard,
what is your situation?
We'll go into that later.
Right now, I must speak to
Lieutenant Commander Data.
DATA:
I am here, sir.
Data, the Bynars have stored
an enormous amount of
material in our computer.
We need to access
it and we can't.
The access would be available
by code or password.
Yes, I know that, Data,
but what could it be?
File names can be anything, sir.
They want us to find it.
They would have kept it simple.
Then a name or a place.
It could be something personal.
In this case,
in binary language,
which is ones and zeros
in groups of eight
or 16 characters.
Would they have kept it
that simple?
Try it. Picard out.
( keypad beeping )
That's the file.
It'll work now.
Now access the file.
Start the transfer.
So much for that idea.
PICARD:
Let me get on the
other position.
The Bynars
always work in pairs.
Maybe that is
also required.
Uh-huh.
It appears to be successful.
Their system has started up.
Their resident diagnostic
program is running.
Their system
is absolutely incredible.
( rapid binary chattering )
-Our world
-is reactivated.
-Our people
-express their gratitude.
-We will return to
-your starbase for whatever
-punishment your system
-requires of us.
Why didn't you just
ask for our help?
( rapid binary chattering )
-You might have
-said no.
There was a chance
we would have said yes.
-Our need was too great
-to risk rejection.
And so you stole it.
Their reason was part
of the binary thinking.
For them there are
only two choices.
One or zero, yes or no.
Why did you lure me
to the holodeck
and hold me there?
-Because we knew we might die
-and we needed someone
-to restore our computer
-and you did.
No one has been hurt.
You've achieved
your objective.
You have your planet
back in order.
We have our ship.
Well, it's been some time
since I had the conn.
But not to worry, Number One.
You're in good hands.
Starbase 74.
Warp two.
Engage.
Everything's under control.
CREWMAN:
USS Enterprise has cleared
the starbase perimeter.
Is everything all right?
We're fine.
Everything is in order.
But now I want a complete check:
all systems, all divisions.
What about the Bynars?
Hand them over to Quinteros.
There will be a hearing.
-We understood that
-would happen.
Follow me,
please.
While these things
are being checked
permission to leave
the Bridge, sir.
Permission granted.
What is a knockout like you
doing in a computer-generated
gin joint like this?
You're not Minuet.
She's gone.
I tried variations
on the program.
Others appeared,
but not Minuet.
Maybe it was all part
of the Bynars' programming.
But you know, Number One, some
relationships just can't work.
Yes, probably true.
She'll be difficult
to forget.