Captain's Log,
Stardate 41309.5:
We are in orbit
around Persephone V
where I have been sent
to confer
with Admiral Mark Jameson
in regard
to an extraordinary situation.
Starfleet received
this subspace transmission
two days ago, Admiral.
Let's see it, Captain.
On viewer.
I am Karnas,
governor of Mordan IV.
A dissident group
of terrorists have taken
Federation Ambassador Hawkins
and his staff hostage.
They will not
discuss terms with me.
This is a crisis
I cannot resolve.
The terrorists are demanding
a Federation negotiator.
I feel there is
only one negotiator
with the skills
to resolve this situation.
The lives of the hostages
will depend
on Starfleet delivering
this man to Mordan--
Commander Mark Jameson.
Admiral Jameson.
The terrorists have given you
six Earth days
to bring him here
or the hostages will die.
PICARD:
Starfleet cannot
understand
how or why this crisis
has developed.
Mordan IV has finally
gained peace
after decades
of civil war.
40 years of civil war, Captain.
Yes, sir.
Karnas was largely responsible
for the planet's unification
and peace.
Why should he now
be unable to deal
with this rebellious faction?
45 years ago
I negotiated a hostage situation
on Mordan, Captain.
Karnas was a young man then,
but so was I.
He seems to feel that I can
handle the situation again.
I'm detailed to take you
to Mordan IV
as soon as you
can be ready, Admiral.
My wife and I will beam aboard
at 1500 hours, Captain.
Acknowledge.
Received and acknowledged, sir.
Picard out.
Nearly 1500 now, sir.
Well, Number One
let's go and welcome
the Admiral aboard.
Welcome aboard, Admiral.
This is my executive officer,
Commander William Riker.
My pleasure, sir.
Ma'am.
My wife, Anne.
Captain, there are certain
details of this mission
that you should understand
before we begin.
Yes, sir.
I am not simply
an advisor.
On any assignment
I accompany
Starfleet has designated me
Senior Mission Officer.
I control the away team
and all its actions.
Is that understood?
Of course, Captain
you command the ship
but the mission is mine.
I trust you are
in full agreement.
Yes, sir.
Of course.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Message coming in
from Mordan, sir.
Put it on the
screen, Mr. Data.
Mordan IV to Enterprise.
This is Karnas.
I will speak to the Captain.
I am Captain Picard
commanding
the Enterprise.
Is Admiral Jameson on board?
He's here beside
my First Officer.
Do you wish to
speak to him now?
So, Jameson, I see time
has not been kind.
It seldom is, Karnas.
However, we could save
a good deal of it now
if you'll outline
the terrorists' demands.
They insist
all discussions will take place
here on Mordan.
They refuse to speak to me--
only to a Federation mediator.
They say
they will brook no excuses.
If there are any offered
your ambassador
and his people will die...
...unpleasantly.
I believe them.
So should you, Admiral.
Tell them I accept
the conditions of negotiation.
I will do so immediately.
For a man in his position
he doesn't seem to know much
about the situation.
Wrong, Number One.
He told me that the terrorists
are desperate enough to kill
if they are crossed.
They are willing
to talk one on one
but not to him.
Counselor?
From his body language
as well as
his words and tone
I judge that what
Karnas said was honest
but I sensed
a holding back.
Perhaps he knows more
about the terrorists
than he's prepared to admit.
Possible, but I suspect
it's closer to the mark
if we said
he doesn't want to admit
failure of his own
efforts to negotiate.
He is
a proud man.
That could be, sir.
Karnas has established
himself as a powerful man
on Mordan.
Suddenly, in this situation,
his power is useless.
BEVERLY:
Sick Bay to Bridge.
I'm ready
for Admiral Jameson now.
In a few moments, Doctor.
Ready for what, Captain?
It's just a routine
medical checkup.
Ship's regulations.
What I don't
understand, sir
is how Karnas knew
that you were still available.
Still alive,
you mean.
So far as he knew, sir,
you could have been dead.
Quite right, Commander,
but I am not
and I imagine Ambassador Hawkins
has told him that.
I briefed the ambassador
about Mordan
before he left
to take up residence.
PICARD:
All right, Karnas
has a problem
he thinks you
can resolve.
What do the terrorists need
that Karnas can't
or won't give them?
DATA:
Mordan's had peace
for five years.
They have finally come
to a state of productivity
which satisfies
their planetary needs
but no more than that.
Perhaps the dissidents
feel the Federation
could provide them with more.
JAMESON:
I have negotiated
many treaties
on many planets, Picard.
I have found that peace
or the appearance of it
is often a prelude to war.
Admiral, are you suggesting
the terrorists want arms
and weapons?
They may.
I am suggesting that Karnas
is the last man to give them
such weapons.
TROI:
I see. You believe
that Karnas
would not negotiate
on that point
and so the terrorists demanded
an outside negotiator.
I know Karnas.
He is a warrior.
He lives for challenge.
These people have
insulted his honor
by taking the embassy
staff hostage.
Now, I'll negotiate
but I'll have to be very careful
in dealing with Karnas.
He'll want revenge
for that insult.
( beeping )
Well...
About time.
Couldn't get away
from the Bridge?
Didn't want to.
Feels good to be
on one again.
I'm glad, Mark.
You want me
to help you up?
( groaning )
You're stronger today.
I'm fine.
I feel like a kid again.
This ship is
magnificent.
It even has
family quarters.
( groaning )
Pity we didn't have them
20, 30 years ago.
We could have been together
almost all of your career.
( beeping )
( groaning )
Mark!
I'll get Sick Bay.
No. No.
There's no need.
It's happened
before.
When?
You haven't said anything.
It'll pass.
Just give me
a moment.
See, I'm... I'm better.
It's going away.
What is it?
Do... the doctors know?
Just body changes.
Last checkup
they said I... I'd
have to expect it.
You're sure?
Don't lie to me.
I'm sure.
Oh...
All the medical information
the Admiral provided
is satisfactory, sir.
Excellent, Doctor.
Except for one thing.
The test results he gave me
aren't two days old.
They're two months old.
The medical records coder
always includes the date
as part of the file number.
He lied to me, sir,
and I don't know why.
He is 85 years old, Doctor.
For some, the memory begins
to fail.
He suffers
from Iverson's disease, sir.
That affects the body
not the mind.
Now, I have a gut feeling
he's hiding something.
Now, that is an observation
I would expect
from Counselor Troi.
Doctor.
Doctor, I do respect
your opinion, and...
I want you on the Bridge
for the next day or so.
The Admiral must remain
in the best of health
for these negotiations
and he might require
your services.
Admiral, we're approaching
the Idini Star Cluster.
Would you like
to take the conn
as we make transit?
Thank you, Captain. I would.
( gasping )
Well, Admiral, quite a little
surprise you've pulled on us.
Yes, quite.
Neglected to mention.
I began some new
therapy before... I left.
Seems to be working.
I haven't felt this good
since the last time
I was in space--
the Gettysburg.
All I needed to get me out of
that chair was the thought
of walking the decks
in command of a starship again.
Admiral, you only have
the conn temporarily.
A figure of speech.
Of course she's your ship.
I'll just keep an eye
on her for a while.
The Admiral displayed
a remarkable improvement.
Captain, no one recovers
from Iverson's disease.
There's no known cure.
There have been no cases
where it's gone
into remission.
I have never heard
of any therapy
that would produce
results like that.
Then how do you
account for it?
I can't. All I can tell you
is that the Admiral
has been confined
to his support chair
for the last four years
by the effects of Iverson's.
By all the medical
facts we know
he should never
have walked again.
I want you to look into it,
Doctor-- thoroughly.
Yes, sir.
The terrorists have given you
six Earth days
to bring him here
or the hostages will die.
I don't know how much
more information
you think you can get
from that tape.
Mark!
My God,
what's happened?
It's the new therapy
I'm taking.
It's... it's
working, Annie.
Oh, darling!
Mark...?
I told you I just needed
to get back in space again.
You really are
looking much better.
It's the new treatment.
No.
Come here.
I hope you're heading
for the bedroom.
You stop it.
Darling...
you look like you
looked 20 years ago.
You flatter me.
Now you tell me what the hell
is going on.
( gasping and groaning )
I don't know.
Mark!
( groaning )
Sick Bay.
Medical emergency
in the Admiral's
quarters.
( groaning )
I found traces
of chemical substances
in his blood
and tissue samples
but none of them are
in our pharmacopoeia.
I'm still working
on alien references
to substances
like these.
All I can tell you
is that he's
ingested something
that's strongly
affecting his body.
Specifics, Doctor.
Captain, there's so
many things going on
I can't give you specifics
until I do a lot more tests.
Well, give me
what you have now.
His red cell count
is running riot.
The cellular structure of his
body is radically changing.
We can't make
any decisions on that
until we know
what it's changing to.
His DNA is skewed.
Don't ask me how
but he even
looks younger.
And Captain--
there are absolutely no traces
of Iverson's disease.
You said there was no cure
for Iverson's.
None that we know of.
Well, whatever
these substances
are doing to his body
at least they've
done that for him.
But how or why?
It's too early to say.
Get me some answers, Doctor,
as soon as possible.
Yes, sir.
( door chimes )
Captain.
Mrs. Jameson, I have
to ask the Admiral
some questions.
Ask away.
There's nothing
to hide now.
Admiral, in addition
to your rank
you are a particularly
valuable commodity just now.
Starfleet has a right
to some answers.
I had planned this
for a long time now--
ever since I learned
that I had Iverson's disease--
since it put me
in that chair.
What did you do, Mark?
There is a planet
in the Cerebus system--
Cerebus II--
they say the natives there
have a process
that rejuvenates the body;
gives you your youth back.
Yes, I've heard of that story.
It's a myth.
It's true, Picard.
I am living proof.
Oh, it's dangerous.
The mortality rate
is high, and...
it's very painful.
Aliens are seldom allowed
to obtain the process
but I managed it.
I negotiated a treaty
for Cerebus II some years ago
and they felt obligated to honor
my request for the process.
Obviously it works very rapidly,
but how does it work?
The herb and drug combinations
are self-administered slowly
over a period of two years.
Every response
is different
depending on a being's DNA.
I got enough
for both of us, Annie
but I had to test it
on myself first.
I-I couldn't risk you.
If I died...
well, I was half a man,
so what did it matter?
It would matter to me.
But I was starting
to change, Annie.
It... it was
almost undetectable
but the improvement was there.
And then when this hostage
situation came up
I... I knew I had to be
at my peak to deal with it.
I didn't have time to wait
for the drug
to-to work
naturally.
So you took the whole dose.
I took both of them.
And look at me,
Annie!
Look at me.
I'm-I'm strong, I'm alert, fit.
I'm fitter than you are, Picard
and I'm getting
younger.
The only question I have,
Admiral
is why you thought
it necessary to be young
to negotiate the release
of the hostages--
even willing to put
your life at risk for it.
I'll be on the Bridge, Admiral,
if you want to talk further.
Why didn't you tell me, Mark?
We've always been honest
with each other until now.
Annie, I did it for us.
Oh... oh, I'm sure
you believed that--
until you had a chance
to head up a mission
and to
command again.
And then you just upended
the bottle or whatever it was
and damn everything.
Did you think about me
at all?
I obtained enough of the dosage
for both of us.
But you never asked
if I wanted it.
It's just like you, Mark
to assume that what you felt
was right was the only answer.
But it was the right answer
for me.
It was killing you having
to take care of an invalid.
Annie, what good was I to you?
We can be together again.
Let me go!
I can get you another
supply of the drug.
( door opens and closes )
( communications beep )
Commander Data
I wish to open a communication
frequency to Karnas.
Aye, sir.
One moment, Mr. Data.
Admiral, this is Picard.
May I know the reason
for this communication?
Karnas must have tried
to negotiate with the terrorists
before he was forced
to call on me.
I want all the information
he has access to.
You said Karnas was a proud man,
Admiral, probably sensitive
to his failure
to deal with this situation.
Is it wise to press him on this?
I am the negotiator, Picard.
Karnas will have to cooperate
with me and the terrorists
and damn his sensitivities.
Then may I suggest
a secure channel, Admiral?
A sensible precaution, Picard.
Make it so.
Aye, sir.
Frequency open
and secured.
Karnas.
What is it you want, Admiral?
We're on a secure channel,
Karnas.
You can talk freely.
Who's behind this thing?
You said dissidents.
Yes-- political opponents
who feel the Federation
will disavow me
as governor if...
if they stir up enough trouble
here on Mordan.
Then who is it? Ardan? Gilnor?
They're dead, Jameson--
a long time now.
A long time I thought
you were dead, too.
I almost died a couple of times
on missions
but I always
made it through somehow.
Yes. Now you're coming
back to Mordan
to negotiate for hostages again.
It's almost as though
the 45 years in between
never happened.
You've never forgiven me.
Of course I have.
It-it was years ago.
There are no dissidents,
are there?
No terrorists.
You have the hostages!
And if I have,
you're coming to Mordan, Jameson
and you're going to negotiate
for their lives
and I'm going to ask
a very, very high price.
What if I refuse?
Then the hostages will die.
You've seen
how my executioners work.
They are still as efficient
as they were--
perhaps even more skilled now.
You'll come
even if you don't have
much honor left.
Conn, are we still on schedule
to arrive at Mordan
in 38 hours?
Aye, sir.
We're at warp 4.
Picard, I want to jump
to warp 8
so that we arrive ahead
of our announced ETA.
It will throw Karnas
off balance
and we can catch him
before he's ready.
Ready for what,
exactly, Admiral?
I believe Karnas
has the hostages
and there never were
any dissidents.
What has happened
to bring you to
that conclusion?
That's quite a big jump.
I'm not at liberty
to say, Picard
but negotiations are
no longer the answer.
Isn't the most important thing
the hostages' lives?
And you agree
with that, too, Riker?
I do, sir.
Good, 'cause I plan
to personally lead
the away team
on an armed rescue mission
to get them out of there.
Commander Data
bring up the plans I requested
on the viewscreen, please.
Aye, sir.
Most of Mordan's
principal city
was devastated
during the war.
What was left
consisted largely
of a network
of underground tunnels--
a rat's maze.
When they rebuilt the city
they simply built over
the existing tunnels.
I have it, sir.
Pardon me, sir
but where do these tunnels
come into the picture?
This is where Karnas
held his hostages before
and where I believe
he has them now.
Wouldn't that be
a little obvious, Admiral?
Karnas is a dogged
strategist, Picard--
not a brilliant one.
He sticks to what works.
He will kill the hostages
if we do not get
them out of there.
Therefore you see
this armed raid
as the only option?
You don't agree?
With respect, Admiral,
I would point out
that no one else has heard
or considered Karnas's demands.
The Federation might
view them differently
if they knew what they were.
Starfleet has given
me command of the
away team, Picard
and I intend to use
them as I see fit.
Our anniversary is next week--
our 50th.
In his heart, he's still
the same man you married, Anne.
That's true.
He still
cares for you
despite the physical changes
he's undergoing.
But he's getting younger
and I'm...
well, look at me.
Why did he do this?
Because there are lives
at stake, Mrs. Jameson.
Well, what about our lives?
His and mine.
I was looking forward
to time together finally.
Our retirement.
Now he's
young again
and has his life to live over.
Doctor, she has to know.
Know what?
Anne, your husband...
What is it?
He's not stabilizing.
He may not have that life
to live over.
We'll be at Mordan
in three hours.
I couldn't sleep, either.
I never could
before a mission.
Always wound up
in the observation lounge
staring out at the stars,
thinking.
Perhaps in this case,
rethinking?
Why is this mission
so important to you?
Why did you risk your life
to lead it personally?
I want to save lives, Captain.
Noble sentiments...
but that's too easy an answer.
You've been here before.
You negotiated a release of the
hostages with Karnas before.
Why is it now your answer
is an armed raid?
It's my away team
you're sending in there.
I think there's something
you're not telling me
and I have a right
to know what it is.
Do you know the background?
The Mordanites had
some sophistication
but were still ruled
by family tribal units.
Karnas's father was
the ruling chief
of one of the families.
Another tribe had him
assassinated.
Karnas seized the passengers
of a starliner
and held them hostage
demanding that Starfleet
provide him with weapons
that would enable him
to defeat his rivals.
That's the official record.
Officially the story is
that after two other
mediators were murdered...
I went in
and negotiated
with Karnas
to bring out the
hostages safely.
Are you saying
that's not the truth?
It wasn't my golden oratory
that saved them, Captain.
I gave Karnas the weapons
he wanted.
You did what?
I gave exactly the same weapons
to his rivals.
My interpretation
of the prime directive:
Let them solve
their problems
with those arms
on an equal basis.
And that decision plunged them
into 40 years of civil war.
I didn't know that would happen.
I thought a minor war...
It would be settled
in less than a year.
How would I know
it would take four decades?
But I...
I falsified the records
to Starfleet.
But I lived with that
on my soul, Picard.
63 people came away safe,
but millions died on Mordan
because I delivered
those weapons.
Karnas could have worked
for peace
during those years
instead of continuing the war.
It's not all on your head,
Admiral.
But I started it.
I lit the match.
Now, finally,
I can vindicate myself
if only in a small way.
I came to negotiate
but that isn't
what Karnas wants.
Revenge.
That's why he demanded you
when he knew that you
were still alive.
And I'm not going
to give it to him, Picard.
I'm going to do
what I should have
done the first time.
We're taking the hostages
out by force if necessary.
No deals.
Prepare to
energize, chief.
Belay that.
Admiral, your proper
place is on the Bridge.
I will remind you
one more time, Picard--
I am the Senior
Mission Commander
and I am leading this team.
Sir?
The Admiral is correct,
Number One.
He has that right
but I am the Captain
of this ship
and I have a right
to accompany him.
Riker, you're in command
of the Enterprise.
Energize.
Yes, perfect.
We are in the M-4 tunnel
directly under
the governor's residence.
M-4 is a subsidiary tunnel
but it crosses and links
with several main ones.
I am sorry, sir.
That does not correspond
with the information
in my tricorder.
Your information
is incorrect, Commander.
I know these tunnels
like the back of my own hand.
Keep scanning for signs
of human life-forms.
Karnas held the hostages
in these tunnels before.
He'll do it again.
Captain.
The Admiral is
definitely incorrect.
The tunnel schematics we have
show this to be
a dead end.
It was sealed off
two years ago.
I have no doubt you're
right, Mr. Data.
However, 45 years ago
I'm sure it linked in
with the tunnels
the Admiral
remembers.
Damn!
Geordi?
This is... steelplast, sir.
Fairly recent
installation.
This is the most
direct route.
Set phasers
to cut through it.
( phasers beeping )
( clanking )
If you have
the coordinates
where you think
the hostages are, sir
we could just
beam in over there.
Karnas may not have them
in the same place.
There's no substitute,
Lieutenant
for a little personal
reconnoiter.
Admiral, there's an
infrared light signal up ahead--
steady beam,
straight across
the tunnel,
chest high.
There's another one
at... about waist level.
An alarm trigger or...?
Reset phasers to stun.
( beeping )
PICARD:
Take cover!
( phaser fire )
Sir, look out!
Their phasers, sir.
Set on kill.
Thank you, Mr. Data.
I have heard the sound before.
( groaning )
YAR:
Is he hit?
No sign
of a wound.
Enterprise,
this is Picard.
Six to beam up, now!
The Admiral?
Sick Bay.
"Not good" is a
galactic understatement.
Sir? Karnas again.
On screen.
Enterprise, there has been
an armed intrusion
in the tunnels beneath the city.
Now, that smells of Jameson.
Where is he?
Karnas, this
is Picard.
I'm sorry
to inform you
the Admiral is
critically ill.
That is not my concern.
Sick or well
you have ten minutes
to beam him down.
( communications beep )
TROI:
Sick Bay to Bridge.
Picard.
Dr. Crusher requests
your presence
in Sick Bay immediately, sir.
I'm on my way.
Sick Bay.
What is it, Doctor?
I think you better see
for yourself, Captain.
Picard.
Picard, I have to get to Karnas.
I can't let him out
of my care, Captain.
It's my last option.
The raid failed.
All I have left to bargain with
is myself.
RIKER:
Bridge to Picard.
Picard here.
A new message from Karnas, sir.
If we don't deliver Jameson
in five minutes
one of the hostages
will be executed.
15 minutes after that,
another.
He promises
the method of execution
will be most painful.
Let me go.
If I give myself over to him,
he'll let the hostages go.
It's me he wants.
It means almost
certain death for you, Admiral.
My life for
how many hostages, Picard? 20?
Let me go.
Number One, inform Karnas
we'll be beaming down
in less than five minutes.
Did you say "we," sir?
You have your orders,
Number One.
Aye, sir.
Who are you?
I want Jameson.
Karnas, this is
Admiral Mark Jameson.
This... charade...
will accomplish
nothing, Picard.
Beam down Jameson and the
hostages will be freed.
Continue this
and I promise you
they will die,
and you with them.
Peritor Karnas, you always
were a stubborn man.
I thought you wanted me.
I'm here.
Release the hostages now.
Peritor was my old title.
Why do you call me that?
I warn you, Picard.
This trick is
going on too far.
He has been
coached for some...
some devious reason.
If this farce does
not stop immediately
you and the hostages
will be put to death!
( groans )
Doctor!
( yelling )
I am waiting for an
explanation, Captain.
He is the Admiral, Karnas!
Before we left on this mission,
he administered an overdose
of an alien de-aging
drug to himself. He...
he wanted to face you
with strength again
on even terms.
This is what the drug
has done to him.
This story you are telling
me is unbelievable.
Jameson is a man of more
than 80 years, not this!
I want that old man, Picard.
I want to show him this world
he helped to make
the scars
on old soldiers' bodies
the graveyards
of our young dead
the wasted cities that we are
still rebuilding.
( groaning )
And all of it
caused by him.
As I understand it, Karnas
it was you
who demanded the weapons
to avenge your
father's death.
But Jameson didn't give
weapons to only us.
If he had, we would have quickly
triumphed over our enemies
and there would
have been peace in
all these decades.
I want him to pay for that,
Picard.
( Jameson groans loudly )
Captain, I think Mrs. Jameson
should beam down now.
Enterprise, this is Picard.
Have Mrs. Jameson prepare
to beam down.
Karnas, I asked Dr. Crusher
to bring with her
the visual records we made
of the Admiral's deterioration.
Will you look at them?
You're wasting my time, Picard.
Just a few moments.
You saw the Admiral
on the Enterprise
when he was en route
for Mordan?
Yes.
And you recognized him?
Is this the man
you saw?
This is the man I want.
He's here, Karnas.
Look.
Once he took the compound,
there was no way to stop it.
( gasping )
You'll have to deal
with me, Karnas.
Whatever you wanted from Jameson
isn't possible anymore
and you wanted revenge.
You blamed your war on him
and there's no doubt he had
a lot to do with it
but you had the weapons
and you used them.
You could have tried
for negotiations
for peace on your planet
long ago.
Instead, you chose to fight.
How many of those 40 years
of civil war
are on your head, Karnas?
Jameson must pay
for his crimes.
I have sworn it
to my people.
45 years ago he made
the wrong decision.
He wanted to come back,
to somehow right it
to atone for
what he did.
Now, all he can do is
give himself up to you.
He brought this retribution
on himself.
No!
I don't believe you.
You're shielding Jameson
on the ship
and you're telling me this tale
to save his life.
Peritor Karnas...
There were only two of us
in the meeting.
You didn't even trust
your lieutenants there.
You told me that
old Peritor Sane
had ordered your father's
assassination.
You told me that you wanted arms
to destroy him.
Peace... wasn't on your mind.
All you wanted was revenge
and I gave you the weapons
to do it.
Jameson told you this.
If it is you...
show me the scar.
There!
The blood cut you gave me
to seal our bargain!
It is you.
Somehow... it is you.
( gasping )
Then die by your own weapon!
No.
No, my revenge will be
in seeing you live like this.
( groans )
Such pain.
The compound he took
is forcing his cells and organs
to go further, younger,
and they can't take the stress.
It's like they're imploding.
And I can't give him
anything to stop it.
Can you ease
the pain?
Mark...
can you hear me?
Yes.
I will always love you.
Annie, with the golden hair.
Flatterer.
It's gray now.
I see only the gold.
( groans )
( crying )
Rest, Jameson.
Your long night... and mine...
are over.
The hostages will be freed
immediately, Captain.
I'm prepared
to be cooperative.
The hostages have been freed
by Karnas unharmed
and the body
of Admiral Mark Jameson
has been buried on Mordan
at the request of his widow
and by the permission
of Karnas.
The quest for youth,
Number One.
So futile.
Age and wisdom have
their graces, too.
I wonder if one doesn't
have to have age and wisdom
to appreciate that, sir.
I hope not, Number One.
Mr. La Forge, prepare
to take us out of orbit.
Set course for Isis III.
Aye, sir.
Leaving orbit.