PICARD:
Commander Riker,
report to the Bridge.
On the way.
MAN:
Harry, Harry,
come back here!
( grunts )
What's your hurry, Harry?
Oops.
Sorry, Commander.
I was just...
Harry!
I'm sorry
if he bothered you.
No bother,
Dr. Bernard.
I'm not
going back.
I hate that teacher,
and I hate calculus.
Everyone needs
an understanding
of basic calculus--
whether they
like it or not.
Why?
( console beeping )
BEVERLY:
You're limping.
I had a small run-in
with an aspiring sprinter.
Number One.
Problem, Captain?
More a curiosity.
For the past few hours
we've been tracking
faint energy readings
in an attempt
to locate its source.
It's like following
a trail of bread crumbs.
The path finally led us here
and then stopped--
which is what I knew
would interest you.
What's our position, Geordi?
The Epsilon
Mynos system, sir.
RIKER:
Thank you, Captain.
you're right.
I wouldn't miss this
for anything.
What's so interesting
about this system?
Aldea.
Tasha, I'm surprised you haven't
heard the stories of Aldea--
the wondrous,
mythical world
like Atlantis
of ancient Earth
or Neinman of Xerxes VII--
advanced culture, centuries old,
self-contained, peaceful
incredible technical
sophistication
providing the daily
needs of all the citizens
so that they could turn
themselves over
to art and culture.
Where's it
supposed to be?
That's the myth.
Somehow, as the legend goes
the Aldeans were
able to cloak
their planet
in darkness
and go unseen
by marauders
and other
hostile passersby
who might rob
and plunder.
YAR:
What a wonderful
fairy tale.
Scanners still show
nothing, sir.
Scanners may
show nothing, sir
but I'm sensing
something very strong--
thousands of minds.
From where?
Very close.
All stop
and hold this position.
Aye, sir.
All stop
and hold.
Anything?
Captain, I'm recording
a distortion
in Quadrant 1, mark, 9-0.
On screen.
( screen beeps )
Shields and
deflectors up.
Aye, sir.
( console beeps )
It's Aldea, Captain.
It has to be.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41509.1:
Either by chance or intent
we've been led
to the planet Aldea
which appeared out of nowhere
hidden behind a sophisticated
shielding device.
Sensors indicate
that the shield is
electromagnetic--
a complicated light-
refracting mechanism.
A cloaking device.
Aye, sir.
It's got to be
pretty sophisticated
to hide
an entire planet.
We're being
scanned, sir.
Hmm. We'll let them know
our peaceful intention.
Open hailing frequencies,
Lieutenant Yar.
Frequencies open, sir.
I am Rashella.
Welcome to Aldea.
I, uh...
( clears throat )
I am Jean-Luc Picard,
Captain of the USS Enterprise.
We come in peace.
We know.
We've heard stories about Aldea
but, frankly, I never
believed they could be true.
Our shield has confused
outsiders
for millennia, Captain.
That's a very long time
to have such technology.
Why do you reveal
yourselves to us now?
We are eager to meet in person
to discuss that
and other subjects
of mutual interest.
We're ready anytime.
Excellent.
( screen beeps off,
alarm sounds )
We mean no harm.
Our arrival seems
to have startled you.
It was a little sudden.
I'm Radue--
First Appointee
to Aldea.
Welcome aboard.
Captain, they haven't been
through decontamination.
PICARD:
Our medical doctor
is concerned
that you didn't
go through
the regular transporting
procedure.
You couldn't
transport us.
The only way through
our shield is our way, Captain.
Our cloaking
device may be off
but our shield
is operating.
We've brought you
small tokens of welcome.
And a personal
invitation
to a celebration
on Aldea.
That would be
delightful.
Number One,
assemble the away team.
We will prepare
for your arrival,
Commander Riker.
How do you know...?
...your name?
Well, we've been monitoring
your ship's communications.
We must now
return to Aldea.
Our eyes are very sensitive
to the bright light.
Rashella.
( device beeping )
Amazing!
To exist only
in that dream world of mythology
and then suddenly to be here,
right in front of us.
Now we know
who placed the bread crumbs.
We're not here by accident.
Counselor,
do you sense anything?
They want something from us--
something we value greatly--
so much, that they're afraid
we won't part with it.
( communications beep )
RADUE:
We're ready to receive you,
Commander Riker
and two of your colleagues.
Interesting choices.
I hope that Duana and I
know how
to greet you properly,
Commander.
How do they
cloak the planet?
The theory is simple--
the shield bends light rays
around the planet's contour--
similar to the Romulan
cloaking device
but the implementation
is quite difficult.
WORF:
Captain!
Data, what do you read?
Some sort of
scanning device, sir.
PICARD:
Don't touch him!
This beam is emanating
from Aldea.
Shields up. La Forge,
contact Commander Riker.
Worf, check all decks.
Shields inoperable, sir.
All decks being probed
in a methodical pattern, sir.
All decks, everywhere--
the entire ship?
DATA:
Aye, sir.
LA FORGE:
Can't reach the Commander--
we're being blocked.
Wesley, are you all right?
It was scary
at first
but I didn't really
feel anything.
WORF:
Sir, similar incidents,
all decks...
but only with the children.
Yes, we are an ancient
power, Commander
but we've suffered for it.
Our history is littered
with the deaths
of those Aldeans who wanted
more and more things.
Nothing was ever enough
so we've evolved a very
simple way of living--
for whatever is
taken, something
is given in return.
That seems
an equitable code.
Hmm, it's brought us peace.
Unfortunately, there are very
few of us left to enjoy it.
Why?
That is part of what
we wish to discuss.
We need help from the Federation
to rebuild our heritage.
We need a younger generation,
strong and healthy
following in
the Aldean traditions.
I don't understand.
How can the Federation
help influence your children
in your traditions?
Because we have no children,
Commander.
Rashella was the last child
born on this planet.
And your medical community
can do nothing?
They've tried, Dr. Crusher,
and failed.
Perhaps we can help.
Radue, exactly why
were we invited here?
We propose a trade:
one which would solve
our problem
and give something back
to the Federation.
And the nature
of this trade?
We need some of your children.
In payment, we will
give you information
that would take you
centuries to acquire.
That might be acceptable
to some other races
but, uh, humans are unusually
attached to their offspring.
Our children are not for sale
at any price.
RIKER:
We sympathize
with your situation
but what you ask
is not possible.
And that's your final answer?
That's my only answer.
Now, if there's
some other way
that we could
help you...
I'm sorry you are
so intransigent.
( high-pitched tone )
Still no response, sir.
( beeping )
Wesley!
They've taken my son.
Alexandra!
( plucking notes )
( alarm sounding )
Captain, saucer section reports
six more children are gone.
It's the children.
That's why we've
been brought here.
That's what they wanted.
And that's what
they have!
Status?
Aldean shields still up.
Hailing frequencies open;
no response.
Keep trying.
Counselor, you'll have
to gather the parents.
They'll need to speak
to you as well, Captain.
( communications beep )
RADUE:
Captain,
your children
are with us.
My word of honor--
no harm will ever come to them.
Harm has already
come to them.
Captain, let us begin
discussions
regarding appropriate
compensation.
Compensation?
You have stolen our children
away from...
away from their classrooms,
away from their bedrooms
and you talk about compensation!
You claim to be
a civilized world
and yet you've just committed
an act of utter barbarity!
Captain, we will continue
these discussions
when you've calmed down.
Wesley, I'm frightened.
I know you
are, Katie--
we all are--
but we're going
to be all right.
Everyone knows
where we are
and no one is
going to hurt you.
I promise.
( door opens )
Greetings
Wesley Crusher.
The Custodian indicated
that you would be the leader.
The Custodian?
Who is The Custodian?
The Custodian is not a person.
RASHELLA:
You have been
brought to Aldea
as our guests.
We'll provide anything
you need or want.
We want to go home.
Wesley, all of you have been
chosen because you are special.
Just ask for
anything you want
and you shall have it.
What's happened to Alexandra
and the other children, Captain?
How are you
getting them back?
Toya, sit down.
Don't give in
to fear.
Now, we all knew
what the risks were
when we signed on
and that's the
choice we made.
Now, Captain Picard will
do everything possible
to bring our
children back.
The Aldeans are anxious
to discuss compensation.
Compensation?
That will buy us time.
I've asked Dr. Crusher
to be involved
in these negotiations
as your representative.
Why were these specific
children taken?
We can't be sure.
We do know the Aldeans can't
have children of their own.
Then they won't
let them go easily.
I won't insult you by pretending
that any of this will be easy.
But I can tell you
that the Enterprise
will not leave them behind.
You can be assured of that.
Can we talk
with our children
give them some
reassurance
let them know
that we are here
and that they
will be safe?
I'll do my best
to arrange that.
The last time I saw him,
I yelled at him.
There you are!
I have you now!
Come in.
Don't be alarmed.
The other children have been
assigned to their units.
Units?
A unit is a group
where those of similar talents
and interests live together.
Do you mean
like a family?
RADUE:
Yes, you could
call it that.
We already
have families.
Does Captain Picard
know you're doing this?
We keep nothing
from him.
We've been waiting
for you so long, Harry.
We are artists,
just like you.
We see within you the potential
of what you can be.
I'm not an artist.
You will be
and a great one.
This way, Harry.
Unit B, three, seven, five.
Katie.
I am honored.
Thank you.
Melian is the foremost
musician on Aldea.
Music speaks
its own language.
I know we'll have
much to learn
from each other.
Don't worry, Katie.
You'll be seeing
Wesley soon.
What about me?
Don't I get
a say in this?
Wesley, sometimes
something happens
which you just must accept.
You and the
other children
are now members
of this society.
That will not change.
It is up to you
to make the transition
as easy as possible
for the others.
It's your duty,
because you are their leader.
Help them to accept it.
Because nothing you
or those on the starship
can do can change it.
Because, like you,
we also have no choice.
( laughter )
Where have you
been, Rashella?
Zena and Aran
are waiting to
take Alexandra.
No.
No? I told you that she...
No, Radue.
They can't have her.
I will never let her go.
Any response from Aldea,
Lieutenant?
Not yet, sir.
Captain, Data has found
something interesting.
The Aldean shield
gives evidence of
random fluctuations
weakening its structure
in isolated sections.
Are you saying
that there are holes
in their defense system?
In essence, yes.
I find it surprising that
after all these eons
the Aldeans have
not perfected
their technology.
One would assume,
they'd be aware
of the weakness
and repair it.
Could we beam an away team
through one of those holes?
It's a possibility.
It would have to be
perfectly timed
and there's no guarantee.
We may be
more successful
in deciphering
the code they use
to transport through
the magnetic shield.
Can you do that?
DATA:
Eventually, sir.
I am working on it now
but the number
of permutations
is almost endless.
Keep trying.
While he's doing
that, Number One
I want you and La Forge
to try and find some way
of getting through
one of those holes
because... one way
or another
we have got to
get an away team
on the planet
to locate power source
for the shield
and neutralize it.
You're certain
they'll negotiate?
Oh, they'll
negotiate
or they'll call it that.
They've taken
what they want.
Now they'll rationalize it
by throwing us
some sort of bone.
And when we don't
accept their offer?
The minute that they believe
that we won't accept
their compensation
for the children
they'll break off
the discussion
they'll disappear
behind their shield
locking us out,
and the children in--
forever.
That's why I've got
to keep them talking.
Custodian.
Wesley Crusher's voice
will be entered
into the authorized file
for third-level clearance.
CUSTODIAN:
Proceed, Duana.
Announce yourself
to The Custodian.
Hello, Custodian.
I am Wesley Crusher.
Hello, Wesley.
Your voice will now activate
third-level clearance.
What does that mean?
You may ask any
questions you wish.
Thank you.
Duana, what does
The Custodian do?
It frees us from all burden.
It takes care of all our needs.
It regulates our lives.
Who built it?
The progenitors.
When?
Oh, hundreds of centuries ago.
What is its power source?
Wesley, why is
that important?
It does what
we ask it to;
it always has.
What difference
does it make
how it works?
If you don't know
how it works
then how can you
repair it?
Why would we want to repair it?
From time to time,
every computer...
I mean, Custodian,
requires maintenance.
Wesley, Radue is right.
You ask questions
I can't answer.
Ask The Custodian
instead.
Custodian
can you show me
where Harry is?
Yes.
Custodian,
show me Harry.
( Custodian beeps )
( instrument buzzing )
I never
did this before.
It's fun.
( laughs )
You are going to make him
into a sculptor?
He already is.
He was just never
encouraged properly.
The tool Leda
is giving him
will allow him
to bring out
his visions.
It will take him years
to learn to do that.
Oh, no
it will happen
quite quickly.
Custodian,
show me Alexandra.
( beeps )
( laughs )
Yeah.
Custodian, show me Mason.
Stop, Custodian.
We must work now.
There's much to learn.
What's in there?
The power source?
I don't know.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
We remain in orbit
around Aldea.
It's becoming all too evident
that talk will not effect
the return of our children.
We must neutralize
the Aldean shield.
Until then,
we are helpless.
Sir, Radue
is hailing us.
( communications beep )
RADUE:
Captain Picard.
Dr. Crusher and I
are ready, Radue.
Are you ill, Captain?
No, Doctor Crusher
is a staff officer.
Starfleet Regulation 6.57
requires that at least
two staff officers are present
during any treaty
or contract negotiations.
Very well.
( communications beep )
Not much on
pleasantries, is he?
Captain, I am not aware
of Regulation 6.57.
No, Data, neither am I.
I see, sir.
Oh, I see, sir.
Dr. Crusher,
please report to the Bridge.
Now we'll see
what they have in mind.
( electrical whine )
Before we begin
we want to see
the children.
No, we're here to negotiate
appropriate compensation
not to pander to emotions.
Please, sit.
We do not condone
your actions.
You're attempting to
salve your conscience
by offering us goods
in exchange for
our children.
Why do you want
them back so badly?
You can always
have more.
You're trifling with
the primal instincts
of our species.
I must warn you
that human parents
are quite willing to die
for their children.
Returning the children
is nonnegotiable.
I promise you, they will have
a beautiful life with us
and they'll be father and mother
to a new breed
born of an ancient culture.
But how can you be so sure
that they can have children?
You can't.
But they will.
Our inability to bear children
is a genetic dysfunction.
It's not
contagious.
We sympathize
with your situation.
Surely, there is a solution
that can be
mutually satisfactory.
For us, the problem
is solved
and we're offering you
information
on areas of the galaxy
you do not even know exist.
What more can we offer?
What more
would you like?
A significant beginning
but first, I must ask
that Dr. Crusher
be allowed to see her son
before we continue.
( laughter )
Oh, you are a stubborn people.
Ah, well, that too can be
a positive trait.
You may see him.
Mom!
Wes.
( clicking )
I knew Captain Picard
would get us home.
Not yet, Wes.
Oh.
Are you okay?
And the others?
Okay, really okay.
We've been assigned
to our units--
like families.
They're treating us
like gods.
( laughs )
Well, don't let it
go to your head.
I won't.
( door opening )
Wes seems fine.
He says the other
children are, too.
Of course
they're well.
Captain Picard,
you have our offer.
It is final.
Rashella.
( electrical whine )
( communications beep )
RADUE:
Captain.
We want you to understand
the nature of your choice.
A small demonstration
of our power.
( whooshing )
( thundering )
( alarm sounding )
( roaring )
( roaring subsides )
( alarm continuing )
What was that?
I believe it was
a repulsor beam.
Position report.
This is unbelievable, sir.
According to my calculations,
we're three days from Aldea.
At warp nine.
And they call that
a "small demonstration"?
Geordi, get us back to Aldea--
warp nine.
Aye, sir.
( communications beep )
RADUE:
Captain--
if you don't accept our terms
the Enterprise will be pushed
so far away
that by the time you return
your children
will be grandparents.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41512.4:
We are 20 hours away from Aldea
and no closer to a solution.
Their deliberate show of force
pushed us out of orbit
and could've easily
disintegrated the ship.
Now hold it a little bit
more firmly.
That's it-- perfect.
Now, think...
No, think's not right.
Feel the notes
inside your head.
( musical discord )
Sorry!
Did I break it?
No, it's all right.
You can't break this.
Did, did exactly
what I thought...
I mean, felt.
Yes, it's a direct reflection
of the music within.
Now we have to teach you
to structure that feeling.
Try it again.
( melancholy tune plays )
That was beautiful.
Now...
play something happier.
That's not
the way I feel.
I don't want to
do this anymore.
( instrument buzzing )
You see, Harry?
I told you, you were
going to be an artist.
Are you sure?
Did I really do this?
Oh, yes.
Your talent
has always been there.
The sculpting tool is just
helping you develop it.
It's what you were
meant to do.
You mean, I don't have
to take calculus anymore?
You don't have
to do anything
you don't want to.
What's calculus?
Nothing important.
Can I do some more?
( instrument buzzing )
Captain's Log, supplemental:
It has been three days since
the Aldeans pushed us away.
We have had no contact
with Radue since then.
Open hailing frequencies,
Lieutenant Yar.
( communications beep )
Frequencies open, sir.
Radue, this is Picard.
( communications beep )
Welcome back, Captain.
What have you decided?
That there is room
for discussion, Radue.
We will bring you down
when we're ready.
( communications beep )
Data, find a way
to defeat that shield.
That may be
impossible, sir.
Things are only impossible
until they're not.
Yes, sir.
Captain...
...here's what
I've learned so far.
Duana is dying.
I have no reason
to believe
the other Aldeans
are any healthier.
They're suffering from
a kind of chromosomal damage.
It could be genetic
or environmental.
And is that why
they can't conceive?
Yes. It also explains
their lack of appetite
extreme pallor
and sensitivity to light.
An entire civilization
that's terminally ill.
Is it reversible?
I won't know
until I find the cause
and you don't need
to tell me--
time is running out.
Good work, Doctor.
Have the lesions gone?
Yes.
The medicine
worked again.
Good.
Come see what
Harry's doing.
Beautiful!
Yeah.
It really turned out well.
It's so alive
and graceful.
What do you call it?
It's a dolphin.
LEDA:
Dolphin?
You know,
it swims in the ocean--
like a fish,
only it's not a fish.
Ah, a fish!
We used to have those
in our oceans.
I've never seen
one before.
I used to live near the ocean
on Zadar IV.
My dad's an oceanographer.
He says that, well...
...never mind.
It... it doesn't matter.
( humming softly )
Shh, shh.
I want Mommy.
Shh, shh...
Shh...
You haven't eaten.
You didn't
eat anything.
We need very little.
We know you
miss your family
but you'll grow
accustomed to us.
I promise you'll be happy.
We were happy before we came.
We are offering more,
especially for you.
Duana...
I feel badly for you
that you have no children
but I have
to tell you
that we don't want to be here
and we will not cooperate.
Custodian's room.
( whispering ):
Custodian, this
is Wesley Crusher.
Proceed, Wesley.
Shh!
Show me where
the Enterprise
children are
in relation
to this room.
( beeps )
Thank you.
Good night.
Good night, Wesley.
( beeps )
( gasps )
Shh!
( whispering ):
I think I know a
way to get us home.
I need your help.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
Stardate 41512.9:
I've begun to suspect
that whatever
is killing the Aldeans
is related to a danger faced
by Earth in the 21st century.
Can it be
that Aldea's ozone layer
has been weakened?
KATIE:
Why will not talking or eating
make them send us home?
It's called
passive resistance.
We don't do
what they want us to do
and they
won't want us.
Will they
get mad at us?
WESLEY:
They won't
hurt us.
But, Wes, I do kind
of like them.
So do I
but I don't want to stay here
forever, do you?
No.
But I like working
with the wood.
WESLEY:
Harry...
we all have to be
in this together
or it's not going to work.
Okay.
I'll do it.
What are you all doing here
together?
What is
going on here?
( console beeping )
I've got it, Captain.
The Aldeans
are suffering
from radiation
poisoning.
Is that what made
them sterile?
Yes.
Is it
reversible?
With proper
treatment, yes.
DATA:
Captain
Sir.
These permutations are going
to take a very long time.
How long?
Weeks.
RIKER:
There is
the other option.
LA FORGE:
We were able
to further define
the weakness
in their shield.
It's not so much a hole
as it is a fluctuation.
If the timing is
precise, it is possible
to beam through
and onto the planet.
Why don't we just beam the
children up through the hole?
The timing would be more
difficult and the risk greater.
All right,
you and Data beam down.
Locate the power source
of that shield.
Knock it out.
I'll, uh, delay the Aldeans
till you're ready.
( giggling )
Shh.
Will you
at least eat?
No, Alexandra.
Why?
We can't eat.
I know
you're hungry--
we all are--
but it's our way
of telling them
that we want to go home.
Understand?
Yeah.
( communications beep )
We're ready,
Lieutenant Worf.
RADUE:
Captain
you may come down now
to conclude our discussion
or your ship may leave.
It's your choice.
Dr. Crusher
and I are prepared
to conclude
our negotiations.
( transporter whines)
( communications beep )
Transporter room, now!
( transporter whines )
This is it, Commander.
It is programmed
to accept only
authorized voice
command.
There's no way
we can override?
No, but I can
scramble the input
so that nobody
else can.
Before we begin, Captain
you must speak
with the children.
It seems they're
on some sort of "strike"?
I don't-I don't
understand it.
You must deal with this,
Captain.
I'm, uh, not very good
with children.
Strike.
I'll see
what I can do.
WESLEY:
I'm sure if we
stick together in this, guys
we'll all be...
Hi, Captain Picard.
Hi, Captain.
Sir, I knew you'd come.
It's not over
yet, Wesley.
I think
I figured out
their computer
controls, sir
but I'm
not sure.
It's a different
system than ours.
Good, Wesley.
Now...
Captain?
Yes, Harry?
If something happens
and you have
to leave us here
will you tell my dad
that I'm sorry
I made him angry
and... that I miss him?
You will tell him that,
Harry
and I will tell him
how much I admire his son.
Hello, Alexandra.
Hi.
( high-pitched beeping )
What is this?
They want
to go home.
No, they're staying.
( communicator beeps )
Number One.
RIKER:
We're in position.
Hold for orders.
BEVERLY:
The radiation
levels on Aldea
have been building up
over a long period of time.
It is similar to what
was experienced
on Earth
in the 21st century
when the ozone layer
deteriorated
and surface
of the planet
was flooded
with ultraviolet
radiation.
The shield that protected
your world in one way
is weakening it in another.
It is the radiation
of your own sun
that is destroying you.
You are trying
to confuse the issue.
Please listen.
You're all suffering
from radiation poisoning.
Sterility is only
the latest symptom.
If the children remain,
they will be affected as well.
That's impossible.
Our scientists would have known.
How could they?
Your scientists have forgotten
how everything works.
No, all lies.
No, wait.
Don't send them
back yet.
What if they're right?
Instead of
the children
being our hope
what if we're
condemning them
to our fate?
Rashella, they're just
protecting their own interests.
As are we.
But hear them out.
The Captain and
Dr. Crusher are saying
that the very thing
which has given us
this wonderful world
is what has caused
this tragedy.
That's it, exactly.
Your Custodian has controlled
you so completely
you've even lost the desire
to question it.
Lies, and the discussion
is over.
( faltering beeps )
( communicator beeps)
Commander Riker.
Yes, sir?
I assume you have control
of the computer.
We've disabled the system
temporarily.
We found the power source
of the shield
and we've neutralized it.
Good.
Enterprise,
this is Picard.
Beam the children up.
Wait.
PICARD:
Enterprise, hold.
Thank you.
Let me get
the dolphin
for you to take
with you.
No, you keep it.
I'll make
another one.
All right, Harry?
Yes, Captain.
Okay, kids,
let's go home.
PICARD:
Beam them up.
( transporter whines )
You have destroyed us.
We're not here
to destroy you, Radue.
We're going to help you.
What is it?
PICARD:
The legacy
of your progenitors, Radue.
The source
of your power
and your problems.
DATA:
It is reading
incredible amounts
of energy, sir.
Even more since we've
taken down the shield.
What are we going
to do with it?
Learn all over again.
All this time we've been
destroying ourselves.
So sure of our
technological
invulnerability.
Now we must learn to use
this power, safely.
Will you let us
help you?
Yes, please.
Dad, I want
to be an artist
but I don't want
to take calculus anymore.
You can be anything
you want, Harry-- anything.
But you still have
to take calculus.
Okay. Thanks, Dad.
It worked well, sir.
We have successfully
re-seeded the ozone layer
but for their atmosphere
to maintain its integrity
they can never
use the shield.
Or be cloaked again.
You finished?
Yes, Captain.
And they're responding
very well to the treatment.
The legend will die
but the people
will live.
And we know they'll
make good parents.
Wesley!
Sorry, Captain.
She just wanted
to thank you
for bringing her home
to her mother.
Thank you.
Come on, Alexandra.
( stifled giggling )
Mr. La Forge
out of orbit,
warp five.
Yes, sir.
Certainly, sir.
( giggling )