Captain's Log,
Stardate 41463.9:
While mapping
the Pleiades Cluster,
we've been asked
by the Federation
to visit a group
terraforming Velara III.
Communications
have been erratic,
and there is some concern
about their welfare.
Entering
standard orbit...
now.
It takes very special people
to live in such desolation.
Visionaries who don't see
the planet as it is
but as it will be.
I've always wanted
to see terraforming
in operation.
Lieutenant Yar.
Hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
Velara III base,
this is Captain Picard
of the Starship Enterprise.
No malfunctioning equipment
on either side, sir.
They are receiving us.
Velara III base,
this is the Enterprise.
Come in please. Over.
Maybe no one's home.
We are sensing life-forms, sir.
Velara III base, do you copy?
Velara base to Enterprise.
Yes, Captain.
I'm Director Mandl,
and I'm sorry about the delay,
but we weren't
expecting visitors.
Terraform Command has asked us
to see how you were
getting along.
We were a little behind,
but we're back on schedule,
and I'd like to hope
we'd be allowed
to maintain that schedule.
We alarm him
for some reason.
Your staff are all well,
I presume, Director.
Understandably tired.
We're working very hard,
Captain.
Well, if there is anything
that we can do to help...
you and your staff
are very welcome aboard
for a change
of scene, rest.
We have some holodecks
which you might enjoy.
No disrespect, sir,
but we cannot afford the time.
COMPUTER:
Channel closed.
His fear is escalating.
If you'll excuse me, sir, I...
I really must get back to work.
I sense deliberate
concealment, sir.
Of what?
I don't know,
but it's intense.
Director Mandl, we've heard
of your remarkable achievements
in terraforming.
My crew would very much
appreciate looking around.
This is not really
the best time.
We're at a very critical phase
just now.
We would require
no special attention.
I'm trying not to be rude, sir,
but this is really
very inconvenient.
He is concealing something.
It's more than
just being too busy.
Your announcement
about coming down
has sent him almost
to a point of panic.
Well, whether he wants us
or not...
Director Mandl,
unless you're absolutely
refusing us permission
to land at your station,
prepare to receive
our away team.
As you wish.
Counselor, perhaps
you'd better go along as well.
Aye, sir.
Someone that tense
can be very unpredictable.
Stay on your toes,
Number One.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Welcome to Velara III.
Please.
I want you to remember it
as it is now
because in a couple of decades,
you won't recognize it.
Luisa Kim,
gardener of Edens.
Commander William Riker,
USS Enterprise.
This is Counselor Troi,
Lieutenant Yar,
Lieutenant La Forge,
Lieutenant Commander Data.
Arthur Malencon,
hydraulics specialist
and Bjorn Bensen,
chief engineer.
An android?
And third in command
of the Enterprise.
Where were you
manufactured?
Are there others
like you?
Both matters are subjects
of protracted discussion.
Remarkable.
Excuse me.
KIM:
We don't get
many visitors.
It's exciting
to have you here.
We weren't sure
how we would be received.
Director Mandl was less than
enthusiastic about our interest.
I should apologize for him.
We are at a critical phase.
Usually, he's quite charming.
We'll try to stay
out of the way.
We've never seen
a terraforming station,
and we appreciate
the opportunity.
How much do you know
about the process?
Theories, reports,
but nothing firsthand.
Oh, wonderful.
Let me show you what we do.
Newcomers find
this imager helpful.
The other two
are secretive,
but she is as open
as she appears.
What we're doing is
so exciting, so inspiring.
We take a lifeless planet
and little by little
transform it
to an M-Class environment
capable of supporting life.
Terraforming makes you
feel a little godlike.
The first phase involves
selecting the planet.
That's very important.
It must have
the right mass and gravity,
a correct rate of rotation,
and a balanced
day and night.
The planet must also
be without life
or the prospect of life
developing naturally.
The Federation
determines if that's so.
Then, we take over.
This station is Phase 2.
Phase 3 involves water.
Usually we create basins
using hydraulic landscaping,
but the water on this planet
is subsurface
and extremely high
in salt content.
We're just about to begin
pumping and filtering the water,
removing the salt,
oxygenating and replacing.
Next, we introduce
microorganisms,
and when the process is complete
we'll have a lush,
arable biosphere.
You make it
sound poetic.
I think it's the best
job in the universe.
The efficiency of your
hydraulic landscaping
is quite elegant.
It isn't yet,
but it will be.
Right now, I'm disturbed
by erratic power surges
in several
of the servomechanisms
that control the
hydraulic probes.
Could the
increased conductivity
be caused by
the high saline content?
That was my first thought,
but I...
BENSEN:
Arthur!
The factors do not
support that conclusion.
I'm Director Mandl,
and I'm sorry
about having been so abrupt
during our initial contact,
but being isolated
one tends to forget
the social graces.
Are you seeing
everything that
you want?
What you're doing
here is miraculous.
What we're doing here
is working a difficult
and demanding timetable,
and there will be no miracle
unless Malencon here
gets the hydraulic probes
back online.
We are set to step up
to full conversion immediately.
Shouldn't you be
in the hydraulic
chamber, Arthur?
Now?
Yes.
All right, Kurt.
Geordi, this appears to be
the master subsurface pump.
You're right.
Very impressive.
This is interesting.
The water table
is a thin ribbon
between the sandy surface layer
and the rocks below.
And those two surfaces follow
that contour so precisely
that the water
maintains a consistent
depth between them.
Which would require
extreme precision
from the probe controls.
Mm-hmm.
Here we have something
that may be of interest
to you--
a vegetation graph.
It is really the key center
for successful terraforming.
RIKER:
Incredible. It's planned month
by month, decade by decade?
Every single thing
is specific and exact.
You see grand,
romantic concepts.
I see unyielding rock
under an
ocean of sand.
Commander!
RIKER:
What is it, Deanna?
Malencon... he's in trouble!
MALENCON:
Help! Help!
( laser bursts )
Help!
Can you open it?
MANDL:
It's jammed.
( Malencon screaming )
( screaming stops )
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 41464.3:
What began as a routine visit
to a terraforming site
has turned into something
far more serious.
Arthur Malencon,
the hydraulics engineer,
has been critically injured
by a laser drill
which appears
to have malfunctioned.
PICARD:
Situation report, Number One.
For safety reasons
we're shutting off all power
to the hydraulics room
before entering
to recover the body.
Then we'll beam him up
to sick bay.
But from the look
of his wounds, it's
probably hopeless.
Keep me informed.
LA FORGE:
Data?
Go ahead, Geordi.
All set.
Data, we have your section
completely powered down.
Bensen has just locked the
master servomotor drive system,
so it should be safe
in there now.
I'm going in.
I will go with you.
Transporter Room,
this is Lieutenant Yar.
Two to beam up to sick bay.
KIM:
I want to go.
We should be with him.
Kurt, please come, too.
Transporter Room,
this is Commander Riker.
Beam up four
at my coordinates.
DATA:
Geordi, this is intriguing.
I have seen malfunctions,
but this is almost
as if the laser drill
seemed to operate with a will
separate from
its control console.
I can't explain it.
The laser blasts seemed to end
when the yelling stopped.
Maybe Arthur stopped it,
only not in time.
Not possible.
Then what are you suggesting?
Uncertain.
Geordi,
please return power to the
control console in this room.
I wish to reactivate
the program.
You got it.
I am now running
the base drilling program.
DATA:
Geordi, servos off!
They are off!
Data, what's happening?
Too much to explain.
Can you open
that? Do it!
La Forge to Enterprise.
We have a problem.
Be specific.
Data's in the
hydraulics room alone,
and we're hearing
laser blasts.
Get him out of there!
It's not working again!
We got to get
this door open.
Data, we can't get in!
Data!
Data! Data!
Away team, now!
What is happening?
I'm going to beam him
out of there!
Bridge, this is
Lieutenant Commander Data.
No need to beam me up, sir.
The situation is under control.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Well, what happened?
Did you do anything
which might have set it off?
No, but the firing program
was dynamic.
The firing pro...
In what way?
It adjusted to my tactics.
It tracked with me,
anticipating.
A fixed program
could not have done that.
Are you suggesting
that someone
was controlling the aiming
and firing sequence?
That is exactly
how it appeared.
There was a mind
working against me.
BENSEN:
What did you do
to this laser drill?
A year's work... destroyed!
I had no choice.
We were attempting to trace
the source of the malfunction
when it attacked me.
How much more of this
useless fantasy
do I have to listen to?
None at all, Mr. Mandl.
Until this is resolved,
I've provided temporary quarters
for you and your staff.
Perhaps you'd like
to make use of them.
You're overstepping
your authority, Picard.
You have no right
to interfere.
Mr. Mandl, an attack on one
of my crew gives me the right.
I have a schedule to meet.
Your schedule is on hold
until I have a satisfactory
explanation of this.
Director Mandl...
Lieutenant Yar, would you escort
the director to his quarters?
Aye, sir.
Go on with your report.
It would appear the
laser's drilling system
was reprogrammed, sir.
As soon as its memory
bank received power,
it turned itself on
and went after me.
Fortunately, I was
able to cope with it.
And not by much,
from what I saw.
I believe it
was programmed
to destroy any person
moving in that room, sir.
Certainty or speculation?
Certainty.
That would have
required the talents
of a master programmer.
But it was done.
And so,
the question becomes not who.
Since it clearly was one of the
three remaining terraformers,
the question becomes why?
What are they hiding?
What could be so important
that one or all of them
could be desperate
enough to kill?
Shall I have them
brought in, sir?
Not yet.
Malencon?
I couldn't save him.
The injuries
were too severe,
the damage
too extensive.
The entire Velara III facility
has been powered down, Captain.
We just completed
a remote power feed
to the life-support systems.
Good. Data, I want you
and Geordi to return for
more careful inspection.
What are we to
look for, sir?
Evidence of tampering,
negligence, sabotage,
whatever...
The answer is there,
on the planet.
Tasha, I want you to provide
Counselor Troi and me
with complete personnel records
of our three guests.
Psych profiles,
training-- everything.
I'm looking for
motive, intent...
the psychological capacity
to commit one murder
and to attempt another.
Aye, sir.
It seems we are becoming
detectives, Number One.
Not much left
of this drill.
Geordi, I need
some visual assistance.
Whoa...
What is it?
Nothing but basic elements.
Inorganic...
no carbon...
sandy texture...
but those flashes
are almost...
musical.
I see color variations
and... rhythms
and complex harmonies.
Speculation--
could it be alive?
How could it be alive?
It's inorganic.
Whatever it is,
it could be what
they are covering up--
and the reason
someone killed Malencon.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
On my order,
Data's startling discovery
of a possible life-form
has been beamed aboard
so that its true nature
might be uncovered,
but unlike life on Earth
and elsewhere
it appears to be
completely inorganic.
A test for inorganic life.
It has never
been done, Doctor.
There are basic
definitions for
organic life.
It must have the ability
to assimilate, respirate,
reproduce, grow and develop,
move, secrete and excrete.
Would any of those
apply here?
Perhaps growth
and development.
Reproduction?
Yes.
Those two may be basic
for any definition of life--
organic or inorganic.
Well, Doctor,
you're charting unknown seas.
So, how do we proceed?
Since we're dealing with
a fundamental question,
let's use the basic
scientific method:
observe, theorize and
attempt to prove it.
Activate.
Let's be sure of what
we're dealing with.
Is the sample organic?
COMPUTER:
Negative carbon.
Negative known life components.
Substance inorganic.
Mm-hmm.
Recheck analysis, please.
Rechecking.
Analysis verified.
Not organic.
Magnify to screen.
Factor five.
Hold surface.
Factor ten.
( soft humming )
What are we
looking at?
It's beautiful,
whatever it is.
What's that hum?
It started after Dr. Crusher
ordered the scanner to magnify.
Computer, demagnify.
Resume normal scan.
( humming gets louder )
Everyone stand back.
( humming softens )
Step back again.
( very faint humming )
It's us.
Yes. We're causing it.
Why?
Unknown, but it is definitely
reacting to our presence.
Perhaps it is picking up
the electrical impulse
of our systems.
The flashes haven't changed.
Could the hum be connected
to the flashing?
Computer, magnify.
What is the magnification?
2500 diameters.
Analyze the pattern
of the flashes.
Not repetitive or sequential.
Pattern not recognized.
What is the source
of the flashes?
Unable to specify.
Theoretically not possible
from this substance.
Disregard incongruity
and theorize as to source.
Life.
What do you mean,
a life-form?
What life-form?
A Federation recon
expedition certified
Velara III lifeless.
Understandable
given this particular
life-form's novel nature.
What is that nature?
Dr. Crusher is still making
her determination.
Mr. Mandl, you know
the Prime Directive.
Are you saying that I
knowingly defied it?
That's what I have to
find out.
You're a man obsessed
with what you do.
Who knows what an obsessed man
will do to keep going.
Kill, perhaps?
I create life.
I don't take it.
You hit him pretty
hard, Captain.
What do you think, Counselor?
It was useful.
I felt two levels.
He did know about the life-form,
but the idea of murder
seemed to shock him.
Whether it was the whole idea
or just being accused of it,
I can't tell.
What about his file,
Lieutenant Yar?
Could he have accomplished
the reprogramming
that Data says took place?
Mandl holds advanced degrees
in computer science
as well as
artificial intelligence.
It's possible.
What about the others,
including the victim?
Well, only the victim had
the required expertise.
Malencon did work
where the...
whatever it is was found.
Trying to suppress
that knowledge
would be motive
for murder
if Mandl were
obsessed enough.
Terraformers are
often obsessive.
It frequently goes
with the career profile.
How do you read
the designer?
She is possessed of highly
abstracted reality.
Lovely visions,
little data.
But you might do
better than I.
( door chimes )
It's not locked.
Mind a visitor?
Is it true?
Did you really find
a life-form?
Well, the debate
is still going on
in some quarters,
but I think so, yes.
What's it like?
We have nothing we
can compare it with.
It's microscopic.
It seems
colonial, simple,
but it's inorganic,
which is why the recon
scouts missed it.
It was not your mistake.
Everything I've worked
so hard for...
...is falling apart.
Luisa.
It's very beautiful.
I could arrange for you
to see it, if you like.
Perhaps later.
Captain, this is Dr. Crusher.
I think you better come
to the medical lab.
What is it?
Geordi observed
movement.
Not movement, exactly,
but a definite shift
in the energy pattern.
Without external
influence.
The hum is gone,
too. Why?
Unknown, sir. Perhaps
it is scanning us.
Scanning us?
Why? What would it
hope to learn?
Unknown at this
time, sir.
It's changing.
I don't see anything.
The infrared range
is increasing.
( humming )
COMPUTER:
Warning. Input overload.
The hum is back.
It is projecting
an energy field.
And it's
intensifying.
( alarm beeping )
Magnification deactivated.
CRUSHER:
Two of them.
Only life can replicate
itself, Doctor.
Inorganic or not,
it is alive.
Activate quarantine field.
Quarantine field, full.
Full shield backup.
Evacuating lab.
COMPUTER:
Translation request
being patched.
Translation? From whom?
( garbled, staticky
computer transmission )
Evacuate.
( garbled, staticky
computer transmission )
What's wrong with the
translator circuit?
Bridge, this is the Captain.
Request emergency
power to initiate
lab quarantine seal.
Do it, Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
What's the nature of
the problem, Captain?
We've lost visual.
We have confirmed
that Data's discovery is life,
but more than that...
it is intelligent life.
How do you know, sir?
It's trying
to communicate with us.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
The inorganic life-form
from Velara III
has apparently taken over
our medical lab.
It generates enough energy
to interfere with the
surrounding systems.
Mr. La Forge,
can we see into the lab yet?
Negative, Captain.
Reducing the backup
to the quarantine seal
might help.
Doctor?
I wouldn't.
Continue quarantine.
Aye, sir.
YAR:
Director Mandl and the others
are in the observation lounge
as you requested.
Counselor,
I shall need you.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
Director Mandl,
I put it to you again.
What do you know
about these life-forms?
Not a thing.
Enough.
Sit down, Lieutenant.
You are deliberately evasive,
and it must stop.
You have kept information
from me
since our first communication.
An alien life-form
has taken possession
of my medical lab.
You knew of
its existence.
Yes.
Is this true?
You knew there was
life on Velara III?
I knew that there were
random energy patterns.
Yes, I knew that,
but not life.
Not by any definition
that I've ever heard.
But you tried to keep
that knowledge from us.
No, they are meaningless
silicon crystals
which rebroadcast sunlight.
It is a life-form,
and it has intelligence.
Why do you say that?
It's trying to communicate
with us.
Communicate with you?
When did you first become aware
of them?
Tell them about the pattern
in the sand.
Oh, yes, do tell us.
When we first arrived,
we noticed that
in certain areas
the sand had
a sparkling effect
like sunlight bouncing off
new-fallen snow.
What did you think it was?
Honestly, we did not
give it any thought.
Picard, I must point out again
that we were assured--
not once, but many times--
by the best scientific minds
in the Federation
that this planet has no life--
no life!
And we were not looking,
and therefore we did not see.
All right,
at first you dismissed it,
but then,
you began to understand
that there was something
that was different
about them.
You can't know that.
Your apprehension suggested it
when we first arrived.
Tell me about these patterns.
At first we thought
it was just natural phenomenon
unique to Velara III.
Refraction
in a thin atmosphere
is interesting
but certainly
not life.
Why was I never
told about this?
Because it's not
particularly important.
As the building
of the terraforming
station went forward,
the patterns in the sand
ceased being random.
They became very specific.
Geometric shapes suddenly
appearing, disappearing,
uh, changing location,
changing size.
Did you ever feel
that these patterns
were attempting to communicate?
No, never.
Bensen?
I don't know.
At the time,
I didn't think so,
but now after hearing
what you just said...
now... I don't know.
RIKER:
Captain, we've regained
magnification on the life-form.
It's divided again.
Patch visual
to observation lounge.
There was no indication
of any of this on Velara III.
Absolutely none.
I cannot understand
the patterns.
Mm, neither can I.
Please show me
spectral analysis--
magnification 12k.
COMPUTER:
Silicon, germanium.
Transistor material.
Gallium arsenide.
Emits light when charged.
Cadmium selenide, sulfide.
Emits charge when lit.
Water, impurities,
sodium salts.
Conductor.
But is it alive?
Probability positive.
I wasn't
asking you.
Engineering to Bridge.
This is Commander Riker.
Go ahead.
The backup on the lab seal
is fluctuating, sir.
I think you should
come down here.
On my way.
Data, you've got the Bridge.
Inform the Captain.
Status, Ensign.
The quarantine seal
is getting weaker, sir.
Every time I try
to redirect backup,
it goes somewhere else.
I think I've...
No, no, it's locked three
people in a turbolift
and two more in the
programmers' restroom.
If that reading is right,
there is no seal.
Give me lab
interior image.
Yes, sir.
Magnify.
Picard, this is Riker.
We see it, too,
Number One.
Get that seal back up!
But, sir, no matter
what I do,
the energy goes
somewhere else.
What if it hits
the sick bay or nursery?
Hold off.
Impossible, Captain.
We haven't got the power.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
The life-form, which has
significantly increased in size
is again attempting
to communicate with us.
The universal translator
is coming online, sir.
Ugly...
ugly... giant... bags
of mostly water...
Bags of mostly water?
An accurate description
of humans, sir.
You are over 90% water
surrounded by
a flexible container.
Life force,
do you understand us?
We understand.
We ask that you be gone.
We call. We talk.
You do not listen.
We didn't hear you.
We come in peace.
Ugly bag of mostly water,
we try at peace.
You still do not listen.
Bag who drilled in sand of home
had to die.
It killed Malencon.
We see and hear you now.
We didn't know you were there.
You are beautiful to us.
All life is beautiful.
Bags in dome did know.
Caused much death.
Make us kill.
War is now with you.
The translator
is offline, sir.
Can you hear us now?
Mr. La Forge?
Restabilizing,
Captain.
Sir, that chaos when we were
studying it in the lab
must have been the energy surge
of a reproductive cycle.
It is now a colony
of single cells
which organize as a computer,
and like any computer...
More is stronger.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
We have regained visual contact
with the lab,
but our attempts
to restore communication
with this microbrain,
as we have come to call it,
have been unsuccessful.
One thing that is certain,
however,
this life-form
has declared war on us.
The range of influence
appears to be concentrated
in the medical lab, Captain.
All nonessential personnel have
been moved
to the most distant areas
of the ship, sir.
Data, any analysis on those
bolts of light it emits?
That seems to be its method
of reprogramming, Captain.
Each bolt of light
consists
of negatively
and positively
charged ions--
a series of program
instructions, as it were.
It seems to have
a quicker rapport
with our computers
than we have.
What do you expect?
It is a computer.
Have we disabled the medical lab
computer console?
Aye, sir. As soon
as Data determined
the microbrain's method
of operation.
Captain, picking up a decrease
in infrared intensity.
Maybe the life-form
has reached its energy level.
Or maybe that's not
the end of it.
With single-celled
life-forms,
at least organic ones,
cell division is preceded
by a resting state.
The calm before the storm.
Medical lab on main viewer.
Let's use this calm.
It does seem dormant, Captain.
Tasha...
set coordinates to beam it back
where it came from.
Coordinates set, sir.
Energize.
Transporter power beam
redirected, sir.
We are unable
to affect it.
Life-form or not,
intelligent or not,
the safety of this ship
and everyone aboard her
is my primary responsibility.
Data...
evacuate all the air
from the medical lab.
I want a vacuum there.
( staticky beeps )
Environmental systems fail
to respond to command, Captain.
It appears the microbrain
has successfully interfaced
with our computers.
Picard, if it did try
to communicate with us,
we didn't
understand that!
It has declared a state of war
and we are on the defensive.
We have no control
over our medical lab,
nor our computer.
At this moment,
it has the power
to destroy this ship
and everybody on it!
I need your help.
Unbelievable.
It said you were trying
to kill some of them.
I need to know how.
I don't know!
What was Malencon doing
when he was killed?
There is a
very thin layer
of highly saline water
under the sandy topsoil.
He was siphoning
that off.
Perhaps somehow that saline
water sustained them.
It connected them.
I don't understand.
The microbrains
may be
like our own brain cells.
Individually, a cell
has life but not intelligence.
Yet when
interconnected,
their combined
intelligence
is formidable.
The saline fluid
is their circuitry.
And to prevent its loss,
they killed Malencon.
If we had continued
to remove that water...
we would have
destroyed them all.
A reason enough
for anyone to go to war.
RIKER:
Captain, it's happening again.
I think
you'd better get in here.
RIKER:
If this keeps up,
it will tear up
the Enterprise.
What can you determine,
Mr. La Forge?
Captain, our
sensors indicate
that the microbrain
expends a tremendous
amount of energy
during its
reproductive cycle
yet there is
no discernible
power drain
on our own systems.
Then, what is feeding
the damn thing?
We found traces
of cadmium salts.
Now, cadmium is a conduit
for converting infrared
into electricity.
Meaning?
Meaning the microbrain
might be photoelectric.
Kill the lights in
the medical lab, Mr. La Forge.
Let's see if darkness
will neutralize it.
Sorry, sir. It still
has control of the computer.
We can't do it
by remote.
Number One.
Aye, sir.
The life-form must have evolved
at that narrow layer
where the light got through
the sand to the water.
Drop the water
a centimeter below
the light penetration level
and they starve.
( electronic whirring )
Killing the lab lights...
now.
It's slowing down.
It's getting
dimmer, too.
MICROBRAIN:
More light, please.
Only if you will talk to us.
We die.
Bags of water kill us.
You are like others.
We have no wish to kill you.
We never have.
You do not say truth.
We will end this war
if you will end the war.
Darkness... death... terrible.
Must go home to wet sand.
War over.
Agreed.
We will send you home
to your wet sand.
Picard to Riker.
Bring up the lights
in the lab...
just a bit.
Are you better?
Better.
PICARD:
We mean you no harm.
Do you believe me?
Yes.
Good.
It is important
that you trust us.
Not yet.
You are still too arrogant,
too primitive.
Come back three centuries.
Perhaps then we trust.
We understand
what you are saying.
We will leave you.
We will send you home.
Riker to Transporter Chief.
Pick up the coordinates
of the bell jar
in the medical lab
for return to Velara III.
Coordinates entered, sir.
Riker to Bridge.
Captain...
we're ready to beam it
back to the planet.
DATA:
I wish we were able
to learn more about them, sir.
In time, Mr. Data,
when we are better prepared.
I wanted to create
a place where living
things could thrive,
and all the while
I was about to destroy
the life that is there.
Our apologies.
And respects.
Lieutenant Yar?
Coordinates set, sir.
Energize.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41464.8:
I have declared an indefinite
quarantine for Velara III,
and we are now returning
to Starbase
with the three surviving
terraformers.
Perhaps the lesson we have
learned from this near tragedy
will prevent it
from happening elsewhere.