Jake!
Jake, wait a second.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
Really.
Jake, I'm sorry.
DR. CRUSHER:
Acting Ensign Crusher,
report to Transporter
Room eight.
It's not your fault.
Yeah, I know.
I wish both of us
were going.
Ah... only 32 points...
Mr. Crusher, respond.
I'm on my way, Doctor.
I've got to go.
I know.
Hey, Wes...
do well for both
of us, okay?
All right.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41416.2:
We are orbiting Relva VII
where Wesley Crusher
is about to be tested
for entrance
into Starfleet Academy.
And to my great surprise,
I have just learned
that my old friend,
Admiral Gregory Quinn,
is on Relva VII
and has requested
to be beamed aboard
the Enterprise immediately.
Welcome aboard,
Admiral.
Thank you.
Captain
Jean-Luc Picard--
Lieutenant Commander
Dexter Remmick.
Sir.
Allow me
to introduce my staff.
First officer,
William Riker.
Chief
Medical Officer
Beverly Crusher.
Chief of Security,
Natasha Yar.
Well, what can
we do for you?
I need to speak with you.
Certainly. This way.
Number One?
Alone.
Is this a personal matter?
Official business.
Well, then,
my first officer should...
Alone, Captain.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Commander Remmick is with
the Inspector General's office.
Oh.
He'll be conducting
a full investigation
of the Enterprise.
What are you looking for?
I have reason
to believe
that there may be something
very wrong on this ship.
Tell me what you suspect.
It's inappropriate to discuss it
at this time.
Mr. Remmick, Starfleet
is counting on you.
You will find out what is wrong
on this ship.
Yes, sir.
Nothing and no one
will stand in my way.
And you,
Captain...
are ordered to cooperate
in every way necessary
with this investigation.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Remmick, unless there are
any further questions...
No questions, sir.
Get on with
your duties.
Yes, sir.
We've known one another
for years.
Tell me what
you believe is wrong.
Captain, it is vitally important
that my orders
be followed exactly.
I'll be staying on the ship.
As you wish, Admiral.
( rapid beeping )
What is it?
What?
The unit you
just put down.
Don't worry,
I won't tell anyone.
It's a flux coordinating
sensor unit.
I'm Oliana Mirren, one
of the other finalists.
You must be
Wesley Crusher.
Yeah.
Do you know me?
I heard there was a very smart,
very young man
who would be
tough competition.
Well, you wouldn't be here...
If I weren't smart.
I know.
But there's a lot more to it
than just that.
You're lucky.
You've had practical experience
aboard the Enterprise.
Oliana.
T'Shanik of Vulcana Regar.
Wesley Crusher
of the Enterprise.
You do not look as if you
meet the age requirements.
I'll be 16 next month.
Oh, happy birthday.
Excuse me.
I'm Wesley Crusher.
Mordock.
Mordock?
The Mordock?
The Benzite who constructed
the Mordock Strategy?
I thought you were
already in the Academy.
No.
Only a hopeful, like you.
Finalists...
please take your seats.
Thanks.
I am Tac Officer Chang.
Welcome.
You are here
because you are all
top candidates.
Although only
one student
will be chosen
for the Academy,
you have shown from
the preliminary testing
that any of you
could easily qualify.
Now, this may be
the most difficult,
exhausting experience
of your life--
and the most exciting
challenge.
Expect...
the unexpected.
May you all do your best.
( computers beeping )
( fast, irregular beeping )
May I help you, Mr. Remmick?
Keep doing whatever it is
you're doing, Commander Data.
There's, uh, nothing much
to see here, Commander.
We're in a standard orbit,
and, uh...
the station has to be manned
even if it's just routine.
Something I can
help you with,
Mr. Remmick?
When I'm ready,
Mr. Riker,
I'll want to speak
with you... privately.
Commander.
Just having that guy around
makes me feel guilty.
What's he after, anyway?
I don't know, Geordi,
but I'm going to find out
right now.
( doorbell chimes )
Come.
Captain,
may I speak frankly?
Always, Number One.
As First Officer,
I should be informed.
I should know everything
that you know.
That's right,
you should.
Then what's this about?
Remmick's going to turn
this ship upside down.
That's his job.
And my job is to see that
this ship runs smoothly.
Which you do very well.
Sir, am I under
investigation?
I don't know.
And if you did?
I couldn't tell you.
I don't understand, sir.
This is extremely frustrating.
No less for me.
But I promised cooperation,
and that's
what we shall give.
Sir.
I want some answers from
you now, Commander Riker...
Later.
You were ordered
to cooperate.
Not now!
When it doesn't interfere
with my duties, Remmick.
COMPUTER:
Last question
on the hyperspace physics test.
If the matter and antimatter
tanks on a galaxy class starship
are nine-tenths depleted,
calculate the intermix ratio
necessary to reach
a starbase
a hundred light years away at
warp factor 8.
Begin.
( beeping )
( beeping speeds up )
( sighs )
Time elapsed.
You now have one hour free
before the next test.
I must admit, Wesley,
you have a very fast mind.
Once I realized it
was a trick question,
there was only
one answer.
Yes. There is only one ratio
with matter-antimatter.
One to one.
You both don't know
how lucky you are.
I can't imagine
what it would be like
to have things
come so easily.
I have to push
every step of the way.
Oh, no, Oliana,
it doesn't come
that easily.
I have to study
all the time.
It's a good thing
you're cute, Wesley,
or you could
really be obnoxious.
See you later.
Did you hear what
she said, Mordock?
She said
I was cute.
Is that good,
Wesley?
Yes.
I think.
I think I should
apologize, Captain.
No need,
Number One.
Mr. Remmick's presence
is unnerving
to say the least.
Are you available now,
Mr. Riker,
or do you still have
duties to perform?
I'm available, Mr. Remmick.
Any problem with using
your ready room, Captain?
No, Mr. Remmick.
Be my guest.
If you prefer to stand,
fine, Mr. Riker.
It won't have an effect
on the length of my inquiry.
Now...
there are several
seeming discrepancies
in the Captain's Log.
Let's go over them
one by one, shall we?
The Captain's Log?
Yes.
( beeping )
To the best of your knowledge,
has the Captain ever
falsified a log?
Have you discussed this
with him?
Right now, I'm asking you.
If you want to discuss anything
about Captain Picard,
you bring him in here,
and you ask him, face-to-face.
You are required to answer
my questions, Mr. Riker,
unless you're trying
to cover something up!
( grunts softly )
Now... there are
several discrepancies
in the Captain's Log.
Shall we go over them
one by one?
Proceed.
REMMICK:
So, you are saying
Captain Picard had
no control over
this vessel.
He handed it over
to Kosinski
who took the
entire crew
to the edge
of the universe.
No, sir,
that's not what I'm saying.
Now, Kosinski was sent here
by Starfleet
to improve
our warp drive system.
Captain Picard was ordered
to take him aboard.
According to his own logs,
his bridge crew
didn't think highly
of Mr. Kosinski's
theories.
Yet, the Captain allowed him
to access the engines anyway.
Is that true, La Forge?
Not exactly, sir.
One way or the other,
La Forge,
Picard lost control
of this ship.
Is that true?
Well, yes, but that's not
how it happened.
So...
the answer is yes.
( beeping )
( sighs )
Do you believe the captain
is emotionally
and psychologically fit
for command of
this starship?
There's nothing in his
history or personality
that would
suggest, uh...
mental lapses?
Nothing.
Not even
the Ferengi incident
aboard his old starship,
the Stargazer?
He was being controlled
by a mind-altering
machine, Commander...
without his knowledge!
I would call that
"a mental lapse."
( beeping )
Ensign.
What are you doing
on the holodeck?
I thought you were
still on Relva VII.
I'm finished testing
for the day.
I've disturbed you.
I'll leave.
Wait.
I thought
I wanted to be alone.
I guess I don't.
How is the testing?
Okay, so far.
It's not the ones
that I've studied for
that I'm worried about.
It's the psych test--
facing my deepest fear
and living through it.
I'm trying to
figure out
what images
to bring up.
Why?
Guess I want
to scare myself.
What do you think?
Bulgallian rats?
Lightning storms?
Do those things
frighten you?
Sort of, I guess.
The psych test is
no more or less important
than the rest
of the process.
That's what they said,
but I can't stop thinking
about it.
Thinking about what you
can't control only wastes energy
and creates its own enemy.
How can they know
what my deepest fear is
when I don't?
By analyzing
your psychological profile.
They were very accurate
about everyone I tested with.
Including myself.
You?
I thought there was nothing
that could frighten
a Klingon warrior.
Only fools have no fear.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
I'm asking
too many personal questions.
It is very difficult for me
to depend on anyone
for anything...
...but especially for my life.
But on the Enterprise,
you do that every day.
Everyone depends on
everyone else to
protect them.
Yes.
So you overcame it?
No. It is still my enemy.
RIKER:
With this new
extricator, sir,
we could eliminate
three more bulky machines
from cargo space.
That's excellent,
Number One.
( alarm blaring )
Captain?
There's
an unauthorized entry
in main shuttle bay.
Unauthorized?
Who is it,
Lieutenant?
Computer reads the ID number
of Jake Kurland.
YAR:
Bridge to main
shuttle bay.
Mr. Kurland, this
is Lieutenant Yar.
Respond.
Isn't that area secured?
Not now, Remmick.
He's going to take
this out, Captain.
YAR:
I'm locking off bay
launch doors, Captain.
Too late. He's using
the flight emergency override.
Smart kid.
Kid?
He's launching.
PICARD:
On viewer.
Lieutenant Yar,
open channel.
( beep )
Enterprise to shuttlecraft.
Mr. Kurland,
this is Captain Picard.
Mr. Kurland?
KURLAND:
Captain, I'm going to Beltane IX
to sign on to a freighter.
Tell my father I...
I'm sorry.
You can tell him
yourself, in person.
Bring that ship
back, at once.
No. I can't face him.
I'm leaving.
( control panel beeping )
( alarm blaring )
Captain, he's unbalanced
the dilithium reaction.
I've lost power.
All he's got left is
his maneuvering jets, Captain.
At this trajectory,
he'll enter the atmosphere
and burn up at an altitude
of 200 kilometers.
Probable impact?
Atmospheric entry,
78 seconds.
PICARD:
Options?
Tractor beam?
Not possible.
He's too far away
for a positive lock.
He's out of transporter range.
Captain, you are
completely responsible
for that boy's life.
Mr. Remmick, either get
out of my way and keep quiet
or I will have you removed
from the bridge.
Viewer on shuttle cockpit.
Visual
on main viewer.
Mr. Kurland?
I can't get the engine
started.
What am I going to do?
I'm going to crash.
He needs
another 50 seconds
for the core to cool down
before he can restart.
Stay calm, Jake.
We'll get you back.
Please, help me.
PICARD:
Jake.
It's no use, Captain.
I'm going to die out here.
He'll need another 30 seconds
before he can restart.
Irrelevant, sir.
Even if he restarts
his engine now,
he will not have enough
thrust to escape impact.
Mr. Kurland, you are not
going to die out there.
You are going to do
exactly what I tell you.
Now... take the nose
of the shuttlecraft
and aim it directly
at Relva VII.
But... aim it at Relva?
I-I can't do that.
That's crazy.
Do it!
But I'll burn up!
28 seconds to impact.
Jake, listen
very carefully.
This is Captain Picard,
and I am giving you an order.
Aim the shuttle at Relva.
( thudding )
Okay.
It's done.
Good.
Now, monitor
your speed exactly.
When it hits .020,
I want you
to restart the engine,
and when I tell you,
pull up hard.
.020 speed.
Captain, I...
I sure hope you're right.
You'll just have
to trust me.
.003...
.009...
.012.
Six seconds to impact.
Hold on, Jake,
it's going to be a little bumpy.
.015...
.019.
Restart the engine, now.
( engine revving )
Pull up hard!
( loud clattering )
( metallic screeching )
Yeah!
Incredible, Captain.
How did he do it?
I-I thought...
He built up
enough speed and then
bounced her off
the atmosphere.
Mr. Kurland?
I assume you can
maneuver it home.
Yes, sir.
Do it. Then report
to Mr. Riker.
Yes, sir.
Very original, Captain.
But how did that child acquire
access to a shuttlecraft?
Kurland is a
highly qualified
Enterprise
Academy candidate--
fully trained
in many areas
including shuttles.
Did this "full training"
include discipline?
Mr. Remmick,
young men sometimes
make rash choices
which is why Mr. Kurland
will receive a strong refresher
specifically in discipline.
I'll note that
in my report.
Mm... full cooperation,
Number One.
( beeping )
You! I have a package
for Operations.
Where is it?
End of the corridor,
room on your right. 104.
Excuse me.
You blocked my path.
You Bulgallian
sludge rat!
I'm sorry.
It was
an honest mistake.
I apologize.
Is there a problem here,
gentlemen?
Uh, no, sir, I...
Look, how dare you?!
I am Rondon,
you despicable
Mellanoid
slime worm!
Liar!
Who do you think
you're bullying?!
You bumped into me!
It was your mistake!
You were at fault!
Do you want this
to become violent?
Friend...
I like you.
A very strange
reaction.
Not really.
When he raised his hand,
I saw that it was webbed--
the sign of a Zaldan.
But you became hostile.
Zaldans are infuriated
by courtesy.
They view it as a form
of phony social behavior
designed to cover
true feelings.
Congratulations, Mr. Crusher.
You handled that
particular instant very well.
Was this incident deliberate?
It's important to know
how you candidates
deal with other cultures,
other species.
Then it was a test.
Yes.
Not all tests are
announced
or what
they appear to be.
Zaldans have webbed fingers.
I wouldn't have passed.
You're an android,
correct?
Yes, sir.
And as an android,
you are programmed to
tell the entire truth?
Yes, sir.
There is a problem with
this ship, Mr. Data.
It's in the records.
Somewhere.
I need your help
to find it.
All of the ship's records
are available to you, sir.
But this information
is very cleverly hidden.
Your captain is not
what he appears to be.
Do not forget that you
have loyalty to Starfleet
above all else.
Loyalty is not
the issue, Commander.
There is nothing wrong
with Captain Picard
or the ship's logs.
Therefore, there must be
something wrong
with your
original assumption.
That is not acceptable,
Mr. Data.
Acceptable or not, sir...
it is the truth.
Just how did
this contaminate
get aboard the ship?
( beep )
By accident, sir.
Meaning Captain Picard
has no standing procedure
for this type of situation?
No.
Meaning by accident... sir.
You don't like me
very much, do you?
Is it required, sir?
How would you characterize
your relationship
with Captain Picard?
We're Starfleet officers
who've known each other
for many years.
Everything said here
is confidential, Doctor.
You can be completely
open with me.
About what?
About how you feel
serving with the man...
who is responsible
for the death
of your husband.
( chuckles softly )
My personal feelings
about Captain Picard
are irrelevant
to this investigation
and none of your business.
Then you confirm
the accuracy of the log report?
You violated the Prime Directive
of the Edo.
You deliberately
interfered with their laws.
Yes. It is exactly
as I explained it
in the log records.
All to save
Dr. Crusher's son.
A member of my crew was
being held unjustly.
I stand by my decision.
( beep )
Mr. Remmick, you've talked
to every member of this ship.
I think you've had
enough time to find out
whatever it is
you're looking for.
Are you afraid
if I keep looking,
I'll find that you're guilty?
The only thing
I'm guilty of
is allowing this charade
to go on so long.
Admiral, if it is me
you're investigating,
ask me directly what
it is you want to know.
And please tell me
exactly what is going on.
I need a little more time,
Jean-Luc.
How much time?
I won't tolerate my crew
being harassed any longer.
Remmick's full report
is almost ready.
I want to be here
when he presents it.
That has always
been my intention.
Commander Remmick,
report to Admiral Quinn.
On my way, sir.
This has been a strain
on our friendship.
I know.
Believe me, Jean-Luc,
I regret that.
But it has been necessary.
( rhythmic computer beeping )
( high-pitched chirping )
I can't get it.
Yes, you can.
Don't fight it.
Relax into it,
and let it come by itself.
No, it's going too fast.
Wesley, I can't do it.
Yes, you can.
You've got your
rotation factor.
Just put in
your vector coordinates.
COMPUTER:
Time elapsed.
( door opens )
Congratulations, Mordock.
That was the second
fastest time
ever recorded on this test.
You all did well.
MORDOCK:
No.
It should not have been
that way.
Mr. Crusher helped me.
Yes, I know.
An interesting choice,
Mr. Crusher--
especially considering how close
you and Mr. Mordock are
in overall score.
You all have an hour
to prepare for your last test.
WESLEY:
The psych test, sir?
We prefer to think of it
as a psychological evaluation
based on reactions to various
individual problems,
but, uh,
"psych test" will do.
Sir?
Please sit down,
Mr. Remmick.
Proceed with your report.
Admiral, I've done
my best to be thorough
during this
investigation.
Continue.
I couldn't find
what you asked for, sir.
I spoke to officer
after officer,
a-at length, I...
pried into
the ship's logs,
and yet I could find
nothing wrong--
except, perhaps a...
casual familiarity
among the bridge crew,
but mostly that comes from
a sense of teamwork...
...and a feeling of family.
I'm sorry, sir.
I did my best.
Quite.
You're dismissed,
Commander.
Yes, sir.
Captain Picard.
My tour in the Inspector
General's office
will be up in six months.
When I'm finished...
this is where
I'd like to serve, sir.
Don't judge the young man
too harshly.
He's a good officer.
It's not him I'm
inclined to judge.
Don't judge me
too harshly, either,
until I've finished.
We had to be
very sure of you.
Some of us
at Starfleet Command
became suspicious of certain
problems in the Federation.
What kind of problems?
Someone or something
is trying to destroy
the fabric
of everything
we've built up
in the last 200 years.
What's your evidence?
I can't go into that.
There are
too many people involved.
What do you want from me?
I don't know whether the threat
comes from the inside,
or whether it's from outside.
I need people I can trust
in strong positions
throughout the Federation.
You have my complete
support, you know that.
That's not enough.
I want to promote you
to admiral,
and I want you to take over as
commandant of Starfleet Academy.
The Academy?
Yes.
I need you close.
Then there was never a problem
with the Enterprise.
No.
But I had to be sure
you hadn't been co-opted.
( snickers )
Then, Greg, uh...
this is...
politics,
and, uh...
( sighs heavily )
...I, uh...
I'm not good
at politics.
Surely there are others
who are better suited.
All right.
Even if I am wrong,
and I hope I am,
you're still the best man
for the job.
I appreciate the value
of what you're offering.
It's not a decision
I can make quickly.
I need an answer soon.
All right.
You'll have it tonight,
Admiral.
Thank you.
Mr. Mordock will be finished
with his psych test momentarily.
WESLEY:
Mordock?
Are you all right?
I will be.
Mr. Crusher.
You're next.
Good luck.
I'm here.
I'm ready.
Maybe they forgot.
Breathe.
Got to remember to breathe.
( muffled thud )
( loud explosion )
( distant yelling )
( alarm blaring )
COMPUTER:
Evacuate immediately.
65 seconds
to seal-off.
Hey, somebody, help!
There's something wrong
in the environmental lab!
( sobbing ):
Help!
( beeping )
Help! We're trapped.
I can't move!
Please, help me!
( moaning )
MAN:
We're going
to die in here!
The liquid hydrogen's
gonna blow.
The shutoff valve's
ruptured. Hurry up!
My legs are crushed!
You've got to help me!
Give me a hand
with this!
We're going to die!
Help me!
I can't!
( hissing )
It's too late!
COMPUTER:
30 seconds to seal-off.
Come on!
If we don't get
out of here fast,
they'll seal us in
to contain the explosion.
Come on!
You're not hurt!
I can't move through that!
Yes, you can!
( moaning )
You've got to!
COMPUTER:
20 seconds to seal-off.
Come on! I can't
carry you both!
You're not hurt!
COMPUTER:
Ten seconds to seal-off.
( yelling )
Come on!
It's too late!
I'm sorry.
( panting )
Officer Chang, there's...
Wesley!
It's all right.
Thanks.
An excellent performance,
Mr. Crusher.
Performance?
That was the test.
Yes.
A man could have died.
Theoretically, yes.
You had to make
a choice, and you did.
There's no right or wrong
about it.
Your greatest fear has been that
you couldn't make that decision.
Because of my father?
Because Capt...
Because someone made
that choice...
and my father died.
Sir?
Yes, Number One?
Mr. Remmick
has left the ship.
Yes.
He found nothing wrong
on the Enterprise.
And you can inform the crew
that Admiral Quinn
is most impressed.
Thank you.
They'll be pleased to hear that.
Can you explain now
what he was after?
They were after me,
Number One.
They want me
to take over
as commandant,
Starfleet Academy.
Congratulations.
What a wonderful choice, sir.
You'll be able
to shape the minds
of the future leaders
of Starfleet.
You haven't decided
what you're going to do.
Yes, I have, Number One.
I've decided
I'm going for a walk.
( door opens, closes )
I'm proud of all of you.
You've done
a superb job.
Each of you would make
a fine
Starfleet officer.
It's unfair that only
one candidate from Relva
will attend the Academy
this year...
and a loss
to the Federation
if the rest of you do not
return to test again.
Mr. Mordock will be
the candidate.
His results were
slightly higher
than Mr. Crusher's.
Congratulations,
Mr. Mordock.
You're the first Benzite
in Starfleet.
Thank you, sir,
but it's not right.
It shouldn't be me.
Wesley lost points
because he helped me.
He should not be punished
for his generosity.
He wasn't.
He lost time,
but it wasn't only that.
Candidates, thank you.
And good luck.
I am sorry, Wesley.
It's okay. You
deserve to win.
Besides, you would have
done the same for me.
Yes. I believe I would.
Congratulations.
Well, personally,
I hate losing.
So you'd better be ready
next year, Wesley.
I won't be
easy to beat.
Mr. Kurland.
Yes, sir.
Are you, uh...
feeling better?
Yes, sir.
Look, I-I'm sorry
I-I damaged
the shuttle, Captain.
But Mr. Riker said
I can work on fixing it
as part of my
discipline training.
Good idea. I hope
you've learned
that running away
solves nothing.
Oh, yes, sir.
And I-I am sorry
I messed up.
But at least
you kept your wits
about you out there.
Don't forget that.
No, sir.
And thank you.
Thank you for-for...
for saving my life.
That's my job,
young man.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Crusher?
Why aren't you in
your dress uniform
for Admiral Quinn's
farewell dinner?
I didn't think that would be
appropriate, sir.
Why not?
I failed, Captain.
I didn't get into
the Academy.
I failed you,
and I failed the Enterprise.
Ridiculous.
Did you do your best?
Yes.
When you test
next year--
and you will
test next year--
do you think your
performance will improve?
Yes.
Good.
The only person you are truly
competing against, Wesley,
is yourself.
Then you're not
disappointed?
Wesley,
you have to measure
your successes and
your failures within--
not by anything
that I or anyone
else might think.
But, um...
if it helps you
to know this...
I failed
the first time,
and you may not
tell anyone.
You?!
You failed?
Yes, but not
the second time.
Now...
you, uh, do me
the courtesy
of joining us
at dinner.
I have to disappoint
an old friend.
Wish I could convince you
to change your mind.
I'll serve you
better here.
This is where
you belong.
If you should
need me...
I've been playing
politics too long.
Perhaps I see
conspiracies everywhere.
Don't worry.
Safe travels, my friend.
Set course for Algeron IV,
Mr. Crusher.
( beeping )
Course plotted
and laid in, sir.
Then shall we continue
with our mission?
Yes, sir.
Excellent.
Mr. Crusher...
engage.