( communications beep )
WORF:
Captain, communication
from Starfleet.
They have recorded
a disturbance in
the Neutral Zone.
Of what nature?
A battle--
in quadrant nine,
coordinates 070, mark three.
There's no information
who is involved.
They are asking
if we can investigate.
Answer affirmative.
Mr. La Forge,
lay in a course.
Aye, sir.
I have no reports
of any Federation vessels
in that area, sir.
Ferengi?
It's a little out of
their territory.
Should we separate
to saucer?
Let's get a little more
information first.
Course set, Captain.
Speed, warp 7.
Aye, sir, warp 7.
Engage.
We are now approaching
the Neutral Zone.
Sir, sensors indicate several
recent photon explosions
and heavy phaser activity.
DATA:
Sir, I have
analyzed the residue
from the explosions.
This is of no known
Ferengi design.
It is possibly Romulan.
Now, there's a name we
haven't heard for a while.
I could go a lot
longer without hearing it.
If the Romulans have
returned to this sector
we should know about that.
Mr. Worf, any
further activity?
Negative, sir.
Slow to half impulse.
Going one-half impulse.
Now entering quadrant
907, mark three.
Shields and deflectors up.
Go to yellow alert.
I have located a vessel, sir.
It is drifting.
Put it on main viewer.
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Magnify.
The life-support systems
on the ship are failing, sir.
Propulsion, navigation and
all communication inoperative.
Any trace of
the other vessel?
DATA:
No, sir.
If it is a Romulan vessel,
it could be cloaked.
Tell Starfleet we're
entering the Neutral Zone.
DATA:
Yes, sir.
Mr. La Forge, take us
in a little closer.
Aye, sir.
Stay sharp, everyone.
It's Talarian.
Life signs?
Nothing yet, sir.
I have identified
the vessel, Captain.
It is the Batris--
a general
cargo vessel.
A long way from home.
Keep alert.
Captain, possible life signs.
What do you
mean, "possible"?
WORF:
The readings emanate from
a location near what is
left of main engineering.
There's a great deal of magnetic
and radioactive clutter
making a positive
determination difficult.
I'll prepare
an away team.
Lieutenant Yar,
you stay at your post.
If this is the result
of a Romulan attack
they may still
be in the area.
Aye, sir.
RIKER:
Data, Geordi-- let's go.
Mr. La Forge,
are we close enough
to use the visual
acuity transmitter?
We can certainly
try it, sir.
Please do.
And Number One...
...everything about this
seems wrong.
Agreed.
It smells like a trap.
Let's go.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41503.7:
We have entered
the Neutral Zone
where a Talarian freighter
has been severely damaged
in a battle.
I have sent an
away team to investigate.
What exactly does
this device do?
Well, Data and I have
been working on a way
to transmit what
my visor sees.
If it works, the Bridge'll
be able to monitor us.
It has restrictions.
The information
from Geordi's visor
is so complex it is
difficult to encode.
Therefore, the signal
breaks down easily.
That means
it doesn't have much range.
Exactly. So far
the effective range
is only a few kilometers,
but we're working on it.
La Forge to Bridge.
WORF:
This is the Bridge.
Worf, I've
switched on
the visual
acuity transmitter.
We are receiving.
The signal is strong.
Okay, Worf, I'm switching
off for transport.
Set phasers on stun.
Let's be ready
for anything.
Energize.
La Forge to Bridge.
PICARD:
This is the Enterprise.
Captain, I'm switching on
the transmitter.
Ready to receive.
Put this on main viewer.
YAR:
Aye, sir.
Extraordinary.
Now I'm beginning
to understand him.
Geordi, what's that?
Over to the left.
What?
Yes, that.
No, no, back.
Yes, that right there.
What is that?
That's Commander Riker.
Ah.
To me, it's just
an undefined form
standing in a...
in a visual frenzy.
Can you...
can you filter out
the extraneous information?
No, I get it all
simultaneously.
But it's just a jumble.
How can you make head
or tail of that?
I select what I want
and then disregard the rest.
But how is that possible?
Well, how, in a noisy room
can you select one
specific voice or sound?
Of course--
something you learn.
Exactly--
something I've learned.
Does that make it more clear?
Look over at Data.
There's an aura around him.
Well, of course,
he's an android.
But... you say that as if you
think that's what we all see.
Don't you?
Sir, I hate to break
this up, but, um...
Oh, yes, uh...
of course, Number One.
Um... proceed.
Let's go.
( steam hissing )
( loud clattering )
( metallic whine )
I am detecting high levels
of deuterium gas.
Probably from the leakage
in the drive system.
Toxic?
Not as yet, sir.
The life signs
are emanating
from the far side
of engineering.
What's the safest
way around?
All routes are
equally dangerous, sir.
Well, what's the least
dangerous route, Data?
There is no
significant difference.
Steady on.
Commander Riker!
Commander!
Yes, Geordi.
There's a fissure
developing in the bulkhead.
The skin of the ship
is losing its integrity.
Where is it? I can't see it.
Right there.
Geordi, step closer.
It looks to me like
a spectrograph
indicating metal fatigue.
Is that how you interpret it?
Very good, Captain.
Exactly right.
How long before
this hull ruptures?
It's impossible
to be exact.
I'd say five minutes--
probably less.
Let's go.
( electronic fritzing )
Geordi,
we've lost transmission!
Signal overload.
I'm surprised
it lasted this long.
( loud rumbling )
We've reached
the core, Captain.
The life signs
are very strong now, sir.
They are coming
from over there.
Is there any other way around?
Negative.
This is
the only way.
The safest way to proceed
is for me to cross alone.
The heat and toxic gases
have less effect on me.
Agreed.
Captain, Data's
gone ahead.
The life signs seem to be coming
from the far side
of engineering.
I found them, sir.
The door to their
compartment is jammed.
The control mechanism
is not operative, sir.
This is Commander Riker
of the USS Enterprise.
Do you hear me?
I advise against
the use of phasers, sir.
The gas buildup
is too great.
He's right, sir.
A phaser discharge
now could blow us
all out of here.
Shall I, sir?
PICARD:
Number One, what's going on?
We're about to
force the door.
( metallic scraping )
PICARD:
What is it?
What do you see?
Klingons.
Klingons?
I am Korris.
We'll handle the
formalities later.
Right now we have to get off
this ship.
Are there any
other survivors?
No.
I believe I have found
a quicker way out of here, sir.
Check him out.
He is alive, sir,
but just barely.
Then pick up the body
and let's get
out of here.
No!
I will carry him.
As you wish.
Come on, let's go!
Tasha, go to
Transporter Room three.
I want you there
when the away team returns.
Aye, sir.
LA FORGE:
Commander, we are out of time!
This ship is blowing!
Transporter Room,
have you got
a lock on us?
Too much interference.
You have to get farther away
from the engineering section.
Sir, the engineering section
is critical.
Destruction of the Batris
is imminent.
They're out of options.
Do it now!
( loud rumbling )
( explosion )
( relieved sigh )
Bridge,
this is Commander Riker.
We are taking
the survivors to Sick Bay.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
Captain...
request permission
to join you.
Granted.
The debris is still
being analyzed.
Inform me as soon
as it's complete.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
( groaning )
Situation, Doctor?
His injuries are
very critical.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard
Captain of this vessel.
My name is Korris
Captain of the Klingon
Defense Force.
This is
Lieutenant Konmel.
Would you mind telling me
what has happened?
We were passengers.
The Talarians were
taking us to outpost
M-Zed-Five.
What was the vessel
doing in the Neutral Zone?
We were attacked
without warning
by a Ferengi cruiser.
During the
course of battle
we must have
unknowingly entered
the Neutral Zone.
The weapons were not
Ferengi.
What is your name?
I am Lieutenant Worf.
And you are a member
of this crew?
Yes.
You are correct.
The weapons were Klingon,
but the vessel
was Ferengi.
What precipitated the attack?
I don't know.
We were in
our quarters.
The captain of the freighter
had no combat experience
so he didn't anticipate
the first attack
which was nearly fatal.
We took control
with his permission.
The Ferengi called
for surrender.
I told the captain
to agree to all their terms.
We had only one chance,
but I was confident
that it would
be enough.
As adversaries
the Ferengi are
not very worthy.
Still, your weapons
were limited
and their vessel
superior.
Yes, all we had
was a battery
of ancient
Merculite rockets.
Our only chance was
to trick them into
lowering their shields.
We reduced power
and lured them in.
They suspected nothing.
Then, when they lowered
their shields
to beam over a boarding party,
we opened fire.
Still, there are some points
that I'm not very clear about.
Captain, we are
hungry and tired.
Of course.
If there is
anything else
you wish to know
about this incident
we will be available.
Permission to
show our guests
to their quarters,
Captain.
Permission granted.
( raspy breathing )
What do you think, Captain?
There's more to this
than we've been told.
Why was a Talarian ship
so far off course?
What was its point
of departure?
Why would three
Klingon officers
hitch a ride
on a broken-down
freighter?
Contact Starfleet.
Find out what they know
about Korris and company.
That'll take 48 hours
for a message to get
to Starfleet
on subspace frequency.
They're going to be
with us for awhile.
Let's find out all
we can about them.
Do you think I should've
assigned a security team
to keep an eye
on our guests?
No, Worf can deal
with anything
that might arise.
How's your
patient, Doctor?
Not good.
I'll keep you posted.
( groaning )
Sit, friend.
Let us eat.
O'mat gri
t'm pffiots.
I did not know
there were Klingons
serving on
human Starfleet vessels.
As far as I know,
I am the only one.
Tell me, what is it
like for the hunter
to lie down
with the prey?
Have they
tamed you
or have you
always been docile?
KONMEL:
Does it make
you gentle?
Has it filled
your heart with peace?
Do glorious battles
no longer inspire
your dreams?
Why do you mock me?
Why do you wish to anger me?
Only to see if it
is still possible.
It is.
Doctor! I think you'd better
come look at this.
( groaning loudly )
The Klingon's
condition is worsening.
He's convulsing.
Get the hypospray.
Damn.
( noisy eating )
( communications beep )
Commander Korris,
this is Captain Picard.
Yes, Captain.
I'm sorry to report
your comrade's injuries
are beyond
our medical abilities.
He's dying.
( ragged breathing )
( exhales loudly )
( low rumbling growl )
( primal roaring )
Is there any
special arrangement
you would like
for the body?
It is only
an empty shell now.
Please treat it
as such.
Be careful.
The opponent
that killed Kunivas
should have
been an enemy.
Then his death would've been
even more glorious.
If the opponent
was not an enemy
who was it?
Tell me,
what really happened?
I do not wish
to anger you.
We are, after all
brothers lost
among infidels.
Tell me, how is it that
you come to this ship
that uniform?
Through an act of kindness.
The Romulans
attacked
the Khitomer outpost.
Everyone was killed.
I was buried under the rubble
and left for dead.
A human Starfleet officer
found me.
He took me
to his home on Gault
and told his wife
to raise me as his son.
How old were you?
Before the age of inclusion.
That young?
Gault is a
farming colony.
When my foster brother and I
were of age
we entered Starfleet Academy.
He hated it
and returned to Gault.
I stayed.
You have not
spent much time
among your
own kind.
Hardly none.
So when the night
was still and quiet
and the sound of the blood
rushing through your veins
filled your ears
the only way
to silence it
was to slip out
into the night
and like the hunter
that spawned you
join in the struggle
of life and death.
You were unable.
And those around you
did not understand.
You frightened them.
They shunned you,
cursed you
called you
vile names
and you knew not why.
Even now do you know
why you are driven?
Why you cannot
relent or repent
or confess
or abstain?
How could you know?
There have been
no other Klingons
to lead you
to that knowledge.
Yes... yes, those feelings
are still a part of me.
But I control them.
They do not rule me.
Yes, to fit in
the humans demanded
that you change
the one thing that
you cannot change.
But because you
cannot, you do.
That too is the
mark of a warrior.
You said
I mock you.
I do not.
I salute you.
But against whom
do you test yourself?
Against what enemy
do you charge into battle?
I have been
in battle.
Then you
understand.
Yes, I do.
Brother, this peace,
this alliance
is like a living death
to warriors like us.
You are right.
We lied
to your Commander.
We commandeered
that freighter
and left the crew behind
and we were in search
of a place
where we could
live our lives
like true Klingons.
You did not
battle the Ferengi.
It was one of
our own cruisers
sent to bring
us back.
You destroyed
a Klingon vessel?!
I did not want to
battle our brothers
but I had
no choice.
They have been
corrupted
by the illusion
of peace.
They traded
our birthright
so they could die
in their sleep.
A peace that makes
the Klingon heart
that beats within my
chest wither and die.
Is it permitted
for you to show us
around this ship?
Yes, of course.
And as I watched Worf
it was like
looking at a man
that I had never known.
Captain, long-range sensors
indicate another vessel
approaching this area.
Can you
identify it?
No, sir, not yet.
Keep a close
watch on it.
So close to
the Neutral Zone
it can't
be random.
CREWMAN:
I want you to have a look
at that sensory data.
What magnificent
battles we could have
at the helm
of this ship.
Perhaps your dreams of glory
no longer fit the time.
They belong buried
with the past.
Standing here
we will never know.
Our answer lies out there.
Our instincts
will lead us.
Instincts that have
not been dulled
by living among
"civilized" men.
I believe, sir, that was
the first time outsiders
have witnessed
the Klingon death ritual.
I can understand
them looking
into the dying
man's eyes
but the howling?
It was a warning.
To whom?
They are warning the dead, sir.
Beware: a Klingon warrior
is about to arrive.
LA FORGE:
Captain
that unidentified vessel
is approaching us
at warp five.
Intersect: one hour,
16 minutes, 33 seconds.
Can we get a visual?
I can try, sir.
Magnify.
Hello.
Klingons.
Open hailing frequencies,
Lieutenant Yar.
Hailing
frequencies open.
Klingon cruiser, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
I am Commander K'nera.
What is your purpose
in this area?
We came to investigate
a battle.
We rescued three
Klingon survivors.
That is all that is left of
the crew of the cruiser T'Acog?
They were not
off the cruiser.
They were from
the freighter Batris.
Their leader
is Captain Korris.
You have him on your ship?
He is alive?
Yes.
He's a criminal, a renegade
who with two others
stole that freighter
and somehow destroyed
the Klingon cruiser
sent to bring them back.
We expect the criminals
to be delivered into our custody
as soon as we are
within transporter range.
Lieutenant Yar...
where are
they now?
They're with Worf
on Deck 17.
Deck 17?
Yes, sir, near the
auxiliary turbolift
to the Battle Bridge.
Shall I alert
Lieutenant Worf?
No, send
a security team.
You don't think Worf
would allow them
access to the Battle Bridge?
I think, Number One, we
cannot assume anything.
Captain, shall I remain
at my tactical position
or lead the security team?
Lead the team,
and, Lieutenant,
you understand
with whom you
are dealing?
Aye, sir.
We have heard this ship
can separate in time of battle.
Yes, when relieved
of its bulk
the Enterprise becomes
an exceptional weapon.
Worf!
They have come for us.
Step aside.
What is the problem?
The Captain wants those
two taken into custody.
KORRIS:
Do not let them
take us, Worf.
Help us.
Listen to the voice
of your blood.
You are not
of these people.
Yes, join us.
Go back!
Please turn around
and go back
to your mother.
Bridge, we have a hostage
situation on Deck 17.
Mommy!
Bridge, this is
Lieutenant Yar--
disregard.
The situation
is under control.
By order
of the Captain
you are confined
to security.
( sighing )
I thought for a minute
we had a problem.
Oh?
Yes, it looked
like Korris
was going to hold that
little girl as a hostage.
That is not our way.
Cowards take hostages--
Klingons do not.
( force field humming )
R'oiaro.
Lieutenant.
A Klingon vessel
has arrived.
They have requested the return
of the renegades.
They will be tried
and executed, sir.
I know.
Lieutenant, understand
I am not unmindful
of the mixed feelings
you must have
about this incident.
Thank you, sir.
Are there no
other options, sir?
None that I can see.
He seems to be handling
this quite well, sir.
So far.
He must be torn.
These are his people.
DATA:
The Klingon vessel
is within range, sir.
They are requesting
visual contact.
Open frequencies.
DATA:
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
We are in position now
to receive the criminals.
We are prepared
to transfer.
WORF:
Captain...
request permission
to address the Captain
on the Klingon vessel.
I know it is against
standard procedure
but there is something
I must say.
Permission granted.
K'omgi bimogus.
G'armond t'ris.
What is it you want?
To plead.
You waste your time.
Their actions threaten
the alliance.
They disobeyed
and must be punished.
Yes, they must be punished
but not executed with dishonor.
Why do you care?
What burns in their eyes
fires my soul.
I hear their words
and I see it all as it was.
Part of me longs for that time.
It's bred in the bone.
We all do.
Then send them to a planet
in the Halee system
where they can meet death
on their feet
with a weapon in their hands,
not tied and helpless.
When one of us dies that way,
it diminishes us all.
Yes.
Brother, I feel as you.
I, too,
wish they could fly free
but I have no choice.
Sir...
We await the transfer.
Lieutenant Yar,
escort the prisoners
to the Transporter Room.
YAR:
Aye, sir.
This is Ramos.
Force field in Security Three
has been broken.
( groaning )
( gasping )
Lieutenant Yar to Bridge.
There's been an escape.
At least one of my security
is dead.
So is Konmel.
Korris is loose and armed.
PICARD:
Keep me informed, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Data, visual on K'nera.
Visual on, sir.
Captain, there will be
a short delay.
Korris has escaped.
He is a trained Klingon warrior,
Captain
perhaps more
than you can handle.
It is not a disgrace
to request our assistance.
I think we can handle
the situation.
( gasping )
CREWMAN:
Stay calm.
CREWMAN 2:
Get down.
CREWMAN:
He's up there!
Captain, Korris is
in main engineering.
PICARD:
Captain Korris
this is a futile attempt.
You cannot win.
I will speak
only to my countryman--
only to Worf!
Captain, he has a phaser
aimed directly
at the dilithium
crystal chamber.
At that range, one blast...
I understand, Lieutenant.
Captain, permission
to leave the Bridge.
We'll both go.
What's the situation?
He's on the second level,
armed with a phaser.
We do not have
a clear field of fire.
How do you suggest
we proceed?
Wait him out.
Captain, let me
talk to him.
I do not think
that's a good idea, Worf.
Right now he's running
on adrenaline.
Let it cool. There's
nowhere he can go.
He will wait
only as long
he believes it is
to his advantage.
The moment it is not
he will fire his phaser
into the dilithium
crystal chamber.
That would destroy the
Enterprise
and him along with it.
Yes, he knows.
Talk to him, Worf.
KORRIS:
Brother!
I knew you would come.
Now I...
we have a chance.
I could not
do it alone
but I would rather die here
than let the traitors
of Kling
pick the meat from my bones.
With you
it will work.
What will work?
I will demand
Captain Picard
give us access
to the Battle Bridge.
We will separate from
the rest of the ship.
Then, together we will
light up the galaxy.
Imagine the fear that
will roll before us.
Captain Picard
will not comply.
He cannot...
dare not refuse us.
In order to save
themselves
they will give us
what we demand.
Then, brother,
we are free.
Put down the phaser.
Wait.
I do not believe this.
Believe it.
I have tasted your heart.
You have been with them
but you are still of us.
Do not deny
the challenge
of your destiny.
Get off your knees and soar.
Open your eyes
and let the dream take flight.
My brother, it is you
who does not see.
You look for battles
in the wrong place.
The true test
of a warrior
is not without.
It is within.
Here, here is where
we meet the challenge.
It is the weaknesses
in here a warrior must overcome.
No.
You have talked
of glory and of conquest
and legends we will write.
Yes--
the birthright of every Klingon.
Yet in all you say
where are the words
duty, honor, loyalty?
Without which
a warrior is nothing!
What are you saying?
Living among these
humans has sucked
the Klingon heart
out of you.
Put down the phaser.
You are a sham.
My words were dust
upon the ground.
Your blood
has no fire.
You are weak
like them.
I don't care
what you look like--
you are no Klingon!
Perhaps not.
( yelling )
Wait.
( ragged breathing )
( exhaling loudly )
( low, rumbling growl )
( primal roar )
( roar stops )
Mr. La Forge, open
hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies
open, sir.
Captain K'nera,
this is Captain Picard.
Yes, Captain?
Korris and the other
Klingon are dead.
May I speak
with Lieutenant Worf?
Yes, Commander.
How did they die?
They died well.
Do you wish the
bodies returned?
They are now only empty shells.
Dispose of them as you see fit.
Worf, when your tour of duty
on the Enterprise is complete
consider serving with us.
Your training and experience
would benefit us
and, perhaps, there are
some things we could teach you.
I am honored.
Thank you.
I was just being polite, sir.
Ah...
Commendable, Lieutenant.
Mr. La Forge
set course
for Starbase 84.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
Really...
I have no desire
to leave the Enterprise.
Good.
LA FORGE:
Coordinates set
in, Captain.
Speed, warp five.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir,
warp five.
PICARD:
Uh, Mr. Worf...
... the Bridge wouldn't
be the same without you.
Engage.