Captain's Log,
Stardate 41798.2.
We have been ordered
by Starfleet
to proceed
to the Lorenze Cluster
and investigate
the disappearance
of the light cruiser
U.S.S. Drake--
which was in that system
trying to unravel
a mystery of its own
which began when recent
long-range probes
indicated that all intelligent
life on the planet Minos
had disappeared.
Number One?
No help from
the communications log, sir.
The Drake reported
arriving at Minos
and then wasn't
heard from again.
Mr. Data?
The citizens of
Minos gained fame
during the Esalrope Wars
as arms merchants.
They manufactured
sophisticated
and highly-advanced weaponry.
Yeah, for which side?
Both.
We are approaching
the planet Minos, sir.
Standard orbit, Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir, standard orbit.
Whatever happened to the Drake
happened quickly.
Otherwise a man like Rice
would have reported again.
You know
Captain Rice?
We were
at the academy together.
Tell me about him.
Able, good officer.
How would he react
under stress?
Paul Rice is confident
to the point of arrogance
but he carries it well
because he's usually right.
He's a risk taker.
Really?
I'll give you an example.
One of the final tests
in Advanced Navigation
at the Academy provides
the students with three options.
Rice was given this test
rejected their options,
and offered one of his own.
That's taking a risk.
And it paid off.
He received the top grade
and now that same test
has four options.
In a difficult situation
a man like that would
act aggressively.
Agreed.
WORF:
Commander.
Weren't you offered
the Drake?
Yes.
You gave up your own command
to take this assignment?
At the time I thought
it would be more advantageous
to do a tour
on the Enterprise.
DATA:
Captain
readings correspond
with the findings of the probe.
No signs
of intelligent life-forms.
Vegetation and
animal life only.
What happened
to all the people?
War?
Disease?
A dissatisfied customer?
In every war, natural disaster,
even the most virulent plague
there are always survivors.
( beeping )
Captain, we are being hailed.
How can that be, from
a planet with no people?
Your sensors indicated
no intelligent life-forms?
Correct, sir.
Something has scanned
our language banks
and is hailing us.
On main viewer.
( beeping )
Whoever you are,
wherever you're from...
greetings.
Welcome to Minos--
the arsenal of freedom.
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the U.S.S....
If you need
a little something...
special, be it for one target
or multiple targets
we got it.
You'll see it, here on Minos--
where we live by the motto
"peace through superior
firepower."
To whom am I speaking?
To be totally armed
is to be totally secure.
Remember, the early bird
that hesitates gets wormed.
It is a recorded
message, sir.
Minos--
the arsenal of freedom.
Perfection in highly advanced
weaponry.
Versatility, flexibility...
We must have triggered
something
left over
from the Erselrope Wars
when the arms business
was booming.
...guaranteed.
So lock onto my signal,
and beam on down
because we don't just
provide weapons.
Shut that off.
We provide
complete weapons syst...
That's a heck
of a sales pitch.
If an automatic message system
is still functioning
there could be other systems
on that planet
that are still operational.
Weapons systems?
Possibly.
We're going to have
to go down there to find it.
Number One,
prepare an away team.
Lieutenant Yar,
Data.
Commander, I recommend
a minimum complement.
Oh? I would have
thought otherwise.
We'll keep the first
landing party small
and mobile until I'm confident
whatever killed the inhabitants
of this planet
isn't still down there.
Okay.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I've ordered an away team
to beam down to Minos
to investigate
the disappearance of the Drake.
Although there are no signs
of intelligent life
coming from this
heavily forested planet
I'm far from certain
that it is devoid of danger.
( beeping )
( bird chirping )
Spooky.
Riker.
This is the Bridge.
We'll start a patterned search
from this point.
Keep this channel open.
Aye, sir.
Commander, our communications
are being monitored.
By whom?
Since there is no intelligent
life, the question is by what?
Captain?
Yes, we heard that,
Number One.
We'll try and track it down
from here.
YAR:
Tritanium.
It's melted.
What could do that?
I don't know, but
whatever it was
it's beyond
our technology.
Over here.
Wow.
We've never seen
anything like this.
It's undamaged.
Maybe a
demonstration model
for some
potential buyer.
Maybe.
Let's spread out
a little.
Commander Riker.
This is Ensign T'su.
I am monitoring a slight energy
buildup near your position.
I'm not able to pinpoint
the source.
Give me a direction.
East of your position,
ten meters.
I will continue monitoring.
I can't see anything
through here.
The underbrush is too thick.
Hello.
Commander Riker.
Rice.
Where did you
come from?
I was over there.
We were worried
about you.
I should have known
you'd pop up.
How are you,
Commander Riker?
Me? Forget about me.
What about you?
No word, no message,
nothing.
How many are with you?
There are two others.
Where's the Drake?
Where's your crew?
PICARD:
Number One, a word.
We have some information
you should be aware of.
Ensign T'su?
Sensors indicate
low-level energy readings
but the only life signs
are the away team.
Do you copy,
Number One?
Understood.
You look strange, Paul.
I was injured getting here.
Do you need
medical help?
No.
What's your purpose here?
Commander Data,
Lieutenant Yar.
Sir, other
than ourselves
I am picking up
no life signs here.
I know.
Riker, you didn't answer me.
Who sent you here
to look for me?
Your mother.
She's worried about you.
Tell me about your ship, Riker.
It's the Enterprise,
isn't it?
No, the name of my ship
is the Lollipop.
I have no knowledge
of that ship.
It's just been commissioned.
It's a good ship.
Refresh me, would you, Riker?
What's its size,
its complement?
Who is here with you?
What's the armament
on the Lollipop?
Paul, I will only answer
your questions
if you answer mine.
Why do you want to know
so much about my ship?
We're friends, aren't we?
Old friends.
Our top speed is warp 3,
what's yours?
"Is"?
Then the Drake has not
been destroyed.
The Drake?
Yes, your ship.
Of course.
My ship is the Drake.
Where is it?
Classified.
Classified?
Please.
It's important.
Our survival depends on knowing.
What's the armament
on your ship?
Ten.
Ten?
I don't understand.
Ten what?
Six.
Commander Riker,
your answers make no sense.
You haven't used
my first name once, Paul.
You remember it, don't you?
You don't, do you?
Because you don't exist.
You're a fake.
You're an image of the original,
aren't you?
Answer me!
PICARD:
Report, Number One.
The image of Rice
has been replaced
by something
which is hovering
several meters away.
Number One,
get your team back up here.
Prepare
to beam up.
( electronic whirring )
Commander!
What's happened, Number One?
Report.
Report, report!
He can't answer you,
Captain.
Commander Riker
has just been encased
in some kind of
energy field.
Is he alive?
Unknown.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Some kind of weapon
which, for a time, took
the form of Captain Paul Rice
has enveloped Commander Riker.
Transporter Room 3.
Have you been able to lock on
to the away team?
MAN:
I am unable to lock on
to Commander Riker, sir.
Ensign T'su,
situation report.
Previous energy
readings are gone.
Data, have you been able
to assess
Commander Riker's condition?
DATA:
He appears to be
in some kind of stasis.
Theorize, Mr. Data.
What would be the purpose
of such an encasement?
Typically, the purpose
of such an enclosure
is for storage.
PICARD:
Which would suggest what?
That sooner or later
someone or something
will be along to collect him.
Stand by.
I'm coming down.
You, sir?
Yes. Dr. Crusher,
this is the Captain.
Meet me in
Transporter Room 3.
Mr. La Forge,
you have command of the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
And whatever
happens down there
your prime
responsibility
is to the ship.
Understood, sir.
Captain, I take exception
to your decision to beam down.
Noted.
Is it just Riker?
Yes. Apparently
he's been confined
inside some sort
of force field.
Energize.
Any changes?
Data's figured
out what it is.
Are you getting
any life signs?
He is alive.
What appeared
in the form of
Captain Rice
is an intelligence-
gathering device
used during the
Erselrope Wars.
Probably developed here.
DATA:
It projects an image
of someone the
subject will trust.
Gets as much information
as possible.
If it's found out,
it encases the subject
to await a more detailed
interrogation later.
Clever.
Can you remove it?
DATA: Possibly.
But I will need to know
the exact frequency
and I cannot
determine the risk
to Commander Riker.
( sighs )
We have little choice.
Whatever has him is interrupting
the transporter beam. Remove it.
( high-pitched beeping )
This will take some time, sir.
( electronic tones )
I am picking up
energy readings.
( beep )
Captain,
Lieutenant La Forge here.
Sensors indicate energy readings
in your area.
Doctor,
over here!
( gasping ):
Oh, no...
Doctor!
( both yell )
( moans softly )
( Picard coughing )
Doctor!
( gasping )
This one is different.
It's anticipating.
Data, I need you.
Set your phaser on kill.
I'll lead left,
you get it.
Captain!
Dr. Crusher?
Captain Picard.
I have a malfunction.
Enterprise, this is Yar.
Mine's out, too.
The close pass
by the weapons
must have disrupted
our communicators.
Keep on working.
I'll look for the Captain
and Dr. Crusher.
Ow, my arm!
How bad is it?
( groans )
It's bad.
( panting )
Hey, come on.
Come on.
All right, d-don't worry.
We'll get you out of here.
Enterprise,
this is the Captain.
Two to beam up.
Oh...
Enterprise!
Enterprise, come in.
Data, Lieutenant Yar.
What's wrong?
Why aren't
they working?
I don't know.
But don't worry.
As soon as they realize
that our communicators
are not working
th-their sensors will find us,
and Geordi will beam us up.
Now, just you hold on.
Uh...
I'm, uh, sorry about this.
( cloth ripping )
Hold on.
It won't be long.
I must keep conscious.
YAR:
Data?
I can't find them.
Step back, please.
I believe I have found it.
Data.
All vital signs
returning to normal.
Good.
Now Geordi can get us
out of here.
Come on.
The Captain
and Dr. Crusher
can't be far away.
( beeping )
Sir, I'm reading
life-forms on
the planet.
All five members
of the away team.
Good. They must have freed
Commander Riker.
Transporter Room
get a lock on the away team,
and beam them up.
Shields just came on.
Deflectors also up.
I'm picking up an object
off the port bow.
It's firing.
Red alert.
Battle stations.
( alarm blaring )
We can't beam the away team up
with our shields in place.
WORF:
Phasers ready.
Photon torpedoes standing by.
Locking on target.
Correction...
target has disappeared.
Give me a full scan.
Scanning.
No readings yet.
Wait. Something dead astern.
Emergency power to shields.
Object is firing.
Return fire.
No use.
It's gone again.
Aft shields weakened.
Whatever they're using
our shields can't stand up to it
much longer.
This is Chief Engineer Logan.
Are we breaking orbit?
I need to know, now!
LA FORGE:
Ship's Log, supplemental.
Lieutenant La Forge in command.
I am unable to beam up
the away team
due to an unseen assailant
attacking the ship.
To make matters worse
Chief Engineer Logan is
on his way to the Bridge
and he's not paying
a courtesy call.
Why are we
still in orbit?
We're taking
a beating.
We've got to hold out
as long as we can.
Now, if can disable
our attacker
if only for a few seconds,
we can drop our shields
and beam the away team
back aboard.
If we follow that plan,
we'll lose the Enterprise.
In view of the
present crisis
I believe you should
relinquish command to me.
No.
I outrank you.
Mr. Logan, I'm in command.
The Captain did not anticipate
the Enterprise
would come under attack.
If he had, would he have
left the Bridge to you?
If he had,
he wouldn't have left the ship!
Picking up an object
to starboard, sir
heading toward us.
Lock phasers
on that thing
and fire the moment
it's in range.
Locking in.
The object has vanished.
Phaser lock lost.
Starboard shields weakened.
It's cloaked itself.
You can't fight this thing
and win.
We've got to break orbit, now!
Worf...
analyze its firing pattern.
Maybe we can anticipate
its location.
Aye.
Solis...
correlate the trajectory
of the energy bolts
with the attack path.
I'll compute
the optimum spread of phaser
and photon torpedoes to hit it.
Right!
Lieutenant
La Forge...
Geordi...
I know you want to do what's
best for the Enterprise.
So do I.
Now, the best thing...
The best thing, Mr. Logan,
is for this discussion to end
and for you to return
to your duties.
Now, I'm in charge
until relieved
by Commander Riker
or Captain Picard.
You're ignoring
my greater rank
and experience.
Not at all.
In fact, just the opposite.
I'm counting on it.
Now, I need you to get
back down to Engineering
and get me every
available scrap
of emergency power you can.
The more power we can
channel to the shields
the longer we'll be able
to hold out.
Now, Mr. Logan.
( sighs )
Worf, have you got
a lock on it yet?
It's impossible
to be sure.
Maybe you should wait here
while Data and I search
for the Captain and Dr. Crusher.
Nah, I'm a
little groggy
but I'll be
all right.
I am getting
energy readings...
Look out!
We'll do it
just like before.
It's got a deflector shield.
The product continues
to upgrade and improve.
We'll concentrate our fire
and try to collapse its shield.
Commander,
we'll need you, too.
Now!
You're right.
They keep on getting better.
The weapons
are appearing
at intervals of
precisely 12 minutes.
Well, this one took
everything we had.
I don't know how
we'll handle the next one.
We're not going
to wait around.
Let's find
the rest of our team.
( water dripping )
We seem to be in some kind
of underground structure.
but I don't see any...
Hey.
No, you don't.
No time to sleep.
I'm tired.
Come on,
stay with me.
Come on, now,
stay awake.
That's an order.
I must have lost
a lot of blood.
I stopped the bleeding.
No, there's
another wound.
My leg.
( cry of pain )
Ah, not to worry.
Everything's going
to be fine.
Now... this is going
to hurt a bit.
I've heard that before.
( moaning )
Hey, hey, Doctor,
stay awake, come on.
There's a lot of blood.
What do I do next?
Doctor.
Uh... the wound needs
a clotting agent.
I couldn't find
your medical kit.
Those roots... what are they?
Roots?
What, these?
Break off a piece
and taste it.
Don't swallow it.
Very bitter.
Apply some to your hand.
Is there
a color change?
It's-It's turning yellowish.
Good. Now, spread as much of it
as you can onto the wound.
Hey, hey, Doctor!
Now, stay awake.
( pounding root )
You've got
to help me.
I need your help.
All right, now listen.
Your patient
has lost a great deal of blood
from multiple lacerations.
The patient's going into shock.
So what do I do?
Elevate the legs,
and try to keep her warm.
Good.
All right?
( groans in pain )
Stay with me, Doctor.
Keep talking.
Well... you didn't happen
to bring a blanket
with you, did you?
No.
I'm going to look
for a way out.
Now, you keep up your end.
Stay awake.
LA FORGE:
All right
I know it's risky
but a shot in the dark
is better than nothing.
Let's see
if we can get lucky.
I can't seem
to pin down
the pattern.
( beeping )
There.
Sorry, sir.
I should have
seen that.
No, that's all right.
You're doing fine.
WORF:
Program laid in.
Phasers and photon torpedoes
ready.
Okay.
Mr. Solis, bring her about
to 23, mark 185.
Aye, sir.
Fire!
Now!
Phasers and photons firing.
We missed!
Number 4 shield
buckling.
Number 3 shield nearing failure.
LOGAN:
Bridge, this is Engineering.
I can't hold this power level
much longer.
You've got to do something!
Backup systems
are overloaded.
Backup systems failing!
LOGAN:
La Forge!
This is Logan.
Tell me something.
Mr. Logan, report to the Bridge.
On my way.
Deflectors are
breaking down.
We have less than
one minute of reserve.
We're getting
out of here.
Lieutenant Solis,
set course 315,
mark 007.
Course set.
You are leaving them
on the planet.
Speed, warp 5.
Warp 5. Aye.
Engage.
Hold course and speed
for 28 seconds
then come to a full stop.
Mr. Logan...
had we stayed,
we would have been destroyed
and there are over
a thousand people on this ship.
I have a responsibility
to them.
What about your
responsibility
to Captain Picard
and the members
of the away team?
I have a responsibility
to them, as well.
Mr. Logan, you are going
to take command...
...of the Saucer Section.
Back up crew,
report to the Main Bridge.
We're going to separate?
Yes, and I want you
to take the Saucer Section
and proceed immediately
to Starbase 103.
You can't fight
what you can't see.
And you still won't be
able to see that thing.
Maybe we won't have to.
Risky.
Yes. That's why
we're going to separate.
Worf, Solis, T'su...
report to the Battle Bridge.
I'll join you in a moment.
WORF:
Ensign, secure
connector levels.
MAN:
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Lieutenant, I need
to speak to you.
Counselor,
we're a few minutes away
from separating
the battle section.
I don't have a lot of time.
I know,
but as counselor
I have a duty
to evaluate
the emotional
fitness of the crew.
And you sense I'm nervous?
Well, you're right.
Counselor, deep down,
I'm shaking.
I'm about to take
this ship into battle
and-and there's a good chance
she'll be blasted
out of the sky.
I'm taking
a huge risk here
and there are
a lot of lives at stake.
So, yeah, I'm nervous.
Did you expect otherwise?
Not at all.
You're under
tremendous pressure
more than you've
ever experienced.
And you think
I'm about to crack?
On the contrary,
you should be proud
of the way
you're handling command.
You've kept a cool
head, taken charge
and made some very
difficult decisions.
Then what did you want
to see me about?
SOLIS:
Lieutenant La Forge
Battle Bridge
is manned and ready.
However, deflectors have not yet
returned to full efficiency.
Let's get them there,
Mr. Solis.
Aye, sir.
I'll join you shortly.
La Forge out.
Did you hear the
uneasiness in his voice?
Solis is doing a fine job.
Yes, but he isn't
handling the stress
as well as you are.
Both he and Ensign T'su
are very young.
No, wait.
They're good officers.
Yes, but they lack
battle experience.
They're worried
about making mistakes
and they need
some encouragement.
What do I do?
Just remember, it's you
they draw strength from.
They look to you
for guidance and
for leadership.
Help them.
Show confidence in them.
Like Captain Picard
showed confidence in me.
Right.
( sighing )
I understand.
Thanks, Counselor.
Prepare to initiate
separation sequence.
All decks
report ready.
On my mark.
Now.
COMPUTER:
Main-latch mags to zero.
Main-latch retraction, 1 to 18.
Initiate.
Static charge, compensated.
Separation complete.
Lieutenant Solis
lay in a reciprocal course
for Minos, warp 5.
Course set.
On my mark.
Engage.
We seem to be pretty well
sealed in, Doctor.
No exits?
None that
I can see.
If you find one, go.
Uh-huh, tired
of my company already?
Beverly?
Beverly?!
I'm tired.
I need to sleep.
Woke up too early.
Talk to me.
Stay awake.
Tell me something.
Tell me about, uh...
about those roots.
How did you know
their medicinal values?
My grandmother.
Your grandmother was a doctor?
No.
Oh, she was a
botanist then?
Uh... no.
She helped to colonize
Arvada III.
Arvada III?
That's such a tragedy.
Did she survive?
Yes.
Once the medical supplies
had run out
she had to use what was at hand.
So she learned
all about roots and herbs
and then
taught it to me.
You were part of that colony.
I didn't know that.
But then there must be
a lot of things about you
that I don't know.
Quite a few.
What?
Now, just a minute,
here's something odd.
It's glowing.
What is it?
I don't know.
It's... it's covered up.
Just... just clearing away
the dirt.
It's a viewscreen.
It seems to
still be
operative.
( buzzing, beeps )
( startup whirring )
( electronic humming )
It's a tracking device
of some kind.
Tracking what?
There are three
moving indicators.
Possibly the away team.
Beautiful, isn't it?
It's the centerpiece
of the whole unit.
Who's that?
A projection.
It's the automated
salesman
who greeted us
on the Enterprise.
What unit?
Why, the Echo Papa 607--
our proudest achievement.
The ultimate
in weapons system technology.
Is that what's behind
the attack on my people?
Impressive demonstration,
isn't it?
Demonstration?
It tried to kill us.
Versatile, powerful,
and easy to use.
The 607
does it all.
Its various modules
can gather information,
neutralize ground personnel
even destroy
enemy space vessels.
The Enterprise.
Is one of those things
after my ship?
Tell me.
Of course I can tell you.
I am programmed to answer
any and all questions
about the unit.
I can talk terms,
arrange for delivery--
whatever you need.
It doesn't understand anything
other than what it's peddling.
The 607 represents
the state of the art
in dynamic adaptive design.
It learns from each encounter
and improves itself.
So what went wrong?
Where are its creators?
Where are the people of Minos?
Once unleashed,
the unit is invincible.
The perfect killing system.
Too perfect.
You poor fools,
your own creation destroyed you.
( electronic whooshing )
What was that noise?
The unit has analyzed
its last attack
and constructed
a new, stronger...
deadlier weapon.
In a moment,
it will launch that weapon
against the targets
on the surface.
Abort it!
Why would I want to do that?
It can't demonstrate
its abilities
unless we let it
leave the nest.
They are down there, sir.
Let's clear
some of that away.
If Data's
calculations
are correct
the next one
should show itself
in two minutes.
Captain!
Can you hear me?
Yes, we're here!
Are you all right?
Dr. Crusher is seriously hurt.
We can't contact
the Enterprise.
The communicators are out.
Yes, our communicators
are out, too.
Those devices
are part of a system
located down here.
Another one is about
to be released.
Watch yourself!
We know, Captain.
It's too far down there.
There's nothing
to hold on to.
There's no way
to climb down.
I'm surprised either
of them survived.
I can do it,
Commander.
How?
Jump.
Data, it's over ten meters.
11.75, sir.
Data...
you may be sturdy,
but you're not indestructible.
I believe I can safely
traverse the distance.
Captain, Data is going
to join you down there.
Be my guest.
Data.
At your service, Captain.
We'd better find
a defensive position.
If Data's right...
He usually is.
We're going to have company
any minute now
and this time, I don't know
how we're going to stop it.
LA FORGE:
Ship's Log, supplemental.
Lieutenant La Forge in command
of the stardrive section.
After separating
from the saucer
we have returned to Minos
to rescue the away team.
Unfortunately, I have
only one option left
and it's a long shot.
Shields and
deflectors are up.
Ensign T'su,
when I order the shields down
you have one responsibility:
locate the away team,
and get them up here.
You may only have a few seconds.
Approaching
the planet, sir.
Ride's going to get
a little bumpy.
Things are going to happen fast.
Just keep alert,
stay calm.
Let's focus on what we're doing.
You know your jobs.
You've been trained,
you've been tested...
and you've earned the right
to sit in those chairs.
( rhythmic beeping )
( electronic whooshing )
That sound again.
Another weapon has
been launched, sir.
We've got to find some way
to stop the system.
I would need to see
the program's schematic.
You've got it.
( beeping whine )
Is it possible
to readjust
the targeting
sequence?
Absolutely.
It wouldn't be much good
without it.
Data, assign it
a neutral target.
Target must be
specific, sir.
Itself, then. Itself
or its own power source.
The force of
that explosion
would destroy
this cavern
and everyone
on the surface.
Watch now.
This is the fourth
and final projectile.
The Echo Papa Series 607
is about to complete
this phase of its mission.
We could split up.
What good would that do?
Confuse it, delay it,
something.
It would still get us.
It would just take
a little longer.
It might give one of us time
to get out of range.
Out of range?
( sighs )
Forget I said it.
These devices wiped out
an entire planet.
I don't think
it has a range.
Then what does
that leave us?
( sighs )
Right. That's
what I thought.
On the other hand,
we could look
for different cover!
( electronic whirring )
You got any ideas?
None.
Give me some options,
Data, quickly.
Why don't you just shut it off?
Is that possible?
Why not?
It's a machine, isn't it?
Shut it off.
Why? You haven't seen half
of what this beauty can do.
We've seen enough.
Does that mean
you're going to buy it?
Yes, yes!
We've seen enough!
You made a sale!
You won't be sorry.
Good! Now end
the demonstration!
Done.
PICARD:
Number One?
Right here.
( sighs )
That was close.
La Forge,
everything's all right.
We've neutralized it.
( crash )
It's great to hear
your voice, Captain
but we're a little busy
right now.
I'll get right back to you.
Phasers at full
readiness.
Keep those shields
at full power.
Ahead one-quarter.
Heading 25
mark 300.
Sir, that heading
will take us further
into the planet's atmosphere.
That's correct. We're going
to lose some maneuverability
so keep a firm hand
on the helm.
Aye, sir.
You hope our attacker will
follow us into the atmosphere.
I'm counting on it.
Lian, scan for any
air disruption or vortex.
Cloak or no cloak
we'll spot it by its turbulence.
Worf, how fast
can you get a
phaser lock?
Fast.
Hull temperature 1,000 degrees
and rising.
Emergency power to deflectors.
Velocity increasing.
Steady as she goes.
Hull temperature
2,500 degrees.
Deflectors nearing overload.
( fast beeping )
Sir, helm's going unresponsive.
Can you compensate?
Yes, sir, I can.
Hull 3,000 degrees.
Maintain heading.
WORF:
We're about to lose
number four deflector.
3,300 degrees.
Deflector four
is now inoperative.
Turbulence to starboard!
There he is!
Scanners locked.
Weapons locked.
Fire!
Got him!
( sighs )
Shields down.
( beeping )
Locked onto away team.
Beaming them home now.
Come to 40, mark 65.
Ahead one-third,
and assume a standard orbit.
Standard orbit.
Aye, sir.
( sighs )
Relinquishing command,
Captain.
As you were, Lieutenant.
Sir?
Mr. La Forge, when I left
this ship, it was in one piece.
I would appreciate
your returning it to me
in the same condition.
You concur, Number One?
Absolutely, sir.
Lieutenant Solis
plot a course to rendezvous
with the Saucer Section.
Sick Bay reports
Dr. Crusher's
going to be fine.
Course plotted
and laid in.
Engage.