All hands, this is the Captain.
As you may know,
a sun in the Delos System
is undergoing large-scale
magnetic field changes
producing violent
gigantic flares.
Now, we shall be studying
this star at close range.
Even though we shall be running
with full deflectors
the closeness of
this event and its severity
will create problems.
Intense
magnetic fields
have a disruptive effect
on electrical systems.
Therefore,
we can expect
communication interruptions
as well as potential temporary
loss of other systems.
As a precaution, we are
now going to yellow alert.
Stay sharp, everyone.
COMPUTER:
Attention all decks.
Yellow alert.
Engineering, this is
Lieutenant Commander Data.
Bring all systems on-line
and direct full power
to the shields.
All sections secure, sir.
Lieutenant La Forge?
Course is set, Captain.
Half impulse.
Aye, sir,
one half impulse.
On main viewer.
Mask out the photosphere.
Magnify quadrant zero-seven
magnification
factor 12.
I've never seen anything
like this before.
The violence of those
eruptions is awesome.
Captain, I'm reading
an unusual number
of sunspots
and eruptive prominences, sir.
The magnetic field
is extremely...
irregular.
Captain, deflectors are being
hit by huge bursts of X rays.
Wow.
Look.
Captain, my console seems
to be overloading.
The X ray burst
is disrupting systems, Captain.
I'm adjusting
deflectors
to compensate.
WORF:
Engineering, increase power
to forward shields.
Forward deflectors on line, sir.
Status report.
All systems operational, sir.
Captain, the level
of tension on the
ship is mounting.
Understandable.
Mr. Data?
If we are to investigate, sir,
we must get closer.
Mr. La Forge...
move us in closer.
Aye, sir.
This is the Captain.
We will be pushing the
shields to the limit
but we are getting
a splendid view
of this phenomenon.
Captain, I've intercepted what
appears to be a distress signal.
Let me hear it.
( static )
This is T'Jon.
I am on the Ornaran freighter
Sanction.
We have a serious problem here
and can't seem to fix it.
( static )
We need help.
The transmission is coming
from a freighter in orbit
around the fourth planet
in the system.
However, the receiving station
is on the third
planet.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing
frequencies open.
Unidentified freighter,
this is the USS Enterprise.
May we be of assistance?
Whoever you are, yes.
I'm having trouble navigating.
Can't maintain a steady course.
Please help us if you can.
Can't you enhance the frequency?
Too much interference.
Set course to intersect with
the freighter-- warp two.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
Maintain yellow alert.
I can't control the helm
any longer.
Our ship is losing orbit.
We're heading
into the atmosphere.
Please do something.
We're going to burn up!
We haven't much time.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
It is a freighter-- very old.
Captain, our sensors are
being severely affected
by the sun flares.
Helm, take us in
as close as possible
to the freighter's orbit.
Moving in, sir.
There are six life-forms
aboard the freighter, sir.
Captain, the freighter's orbit
is decaying.
How long before
it loses integrity?
A matter of minutes.
Unidentified freighter,
this is the USS Enterprise.
T'JON:
Enterprise
this is the Ornaran
freighter Sanction.
Put this on the main viewer.
( static )
The visual transmission
is still breaking up.
Freighter Sanction,
this is the Enterprise.
What is your situation?
Oh, not so good.
The helm isn't working right.
( many voices speaking at once)
This is the Enterprise.
With all this interference
it is difficult to copy
your transmission.
If you all talk at once,
it is almost impossible.
Now, please, say again
what is your situation?
I am T'Jon,
Captain of the Sanction.
At last.
How can we help?
We have lost...
I don't know, something.
I am no longer able
to maintain this orbit
nor am I able
to use the main thrusters.
It's all, you know,
dead I guess.
It's all... shut down.
Well, that is
a little vague.
What is the computer
analysis?
Well, the computer's
not working very well.
Data, can you tap
into their computer
and clarify
the situation?
I will attempt it, sir.
Captain, the tractor beam is
available, if you want it.
At least, we can pull them
out of orbit
before they enter
the atmosphere.
Freighter, we're going to
lock on the tractor beam
and pull you
out of orbit.
Hey, that's great.
( beam trying to power up )
Captain, the freighter's orbit
continues to deteriorate.
The solar flares are interfering
with the tractor beam, Captain.
I can't lock on.
Captain T'Jon, we are unable
to attach the tractor beam
because of the intense
solar activity.
I understand.
Thanks for trying.
Sir, I have determined what is
malfunctioning on the freighter.
Captain, we
have analyzed
your problem.
Great.
Data.
Your ship's design uses
an electromagnetic coil
to constrict the exhaust flow.
That coil is misaligned.
Really?
Do you have the necessary
tools to realign the coil?
I don't think so.
I believe, Captain,
we can provide them
with a temporary substitute.
Our ship's stores contain
a coil of the proper type.
Can we beam one over?
Yes.
Captain, we are beaming over
a replacement coil.
That's great.
And that will fix us up?
Yes, once it's installed.
Right.
And how do we do that?
What is the matter
with these people?
How can he be captain
of that vessel
and not understand
its simplest
function?
Captain, how long
have you been
in command of
this freighter?
Seven years.
This is my 26th voyage
to Brekka.
And you don't know how
to align a control coil?
It's never come up.
Can anyone else
over there do it?
Hold on. I'll ask.
Sorry, nobody here
knows anything about it.
I'd better get over there
with a team.
Captain,
I strongly
recommend against anyone
from the ship beaming over.
The solar interference
is too great.
WORF:
The freighter has entered
the planet's atmosphere.
Disintegration is imminent.
We're running out
of options.
Let's get them off there.
T'Jon, stand by to beam over.
If you think that's best.
Unless you have
any other options
yes, I think that's best.
Whatever you say.
I can't maintain
a positive lock.
Unusual E.M. burst, sir.
Readings off scale.
Freighter Sanction,
this is the Enterprise.
We're having difficulty
getting a fix.
Have them go
to their own transporter room.
It will be tricky
but perhaps I can link
the two transporters
in series
and get them over
with the increased power.
That's worth a try.
Captain T'Jon, go
to your transporter room.
Contact me from there.
Right, Enterprise.
It's right next door
but, if you can't get us
with your transporter
what makes you think
ours will do the job?
I'm going to interconnect them.
I didn't know you could do that.
Hurry!
We're running out of time.
We're on our way.
I don't think
they're going to make it.
Captain T'Jon doesn't
sound like he cares
one way
or the other.
( beeping )
Worf, how much time do we have?
WORF:
One minute, 28 seconds.
Captain T'Jon, are you there?
We're in the transporter room.
Great, activate
your transporter.
Set coordinates
nine-seven-zero-three
mark two-six-eight.
Did you say two-eight-six
or eight-eight-six?
Mark two-six-eight.
Got it.
Sir, the hull temperature
of the freighter
is passing
3,000 degrees.
What's the holdup,
Number One?
We're establishing
the link right now.
We're ready.
Then all six of you get
on the transporter platform.
On my signal, energize.
I've got their initial
transporter signal
interlock complete.
Energize on my mark.
Four, three, two,
one... energize.
PICARD:
Number One,
did you get them off?
No, sir, they stayed
on the freighter
but they beamed over
their cargo.
Cargo?
Are those people crazy?
What could possibly
be so important?
Sir, the freighter
is disintegrating.
Their lives are in danger
and they're beaming over cargo?
Number One, I don't understand
these people.
Captain, freighter's
hull temperature
is approaching critical.
Unbelievable.
PICARD:
We're losing the freighter.
We've got to beam
those people over now.
Clear the cargo,
beam it to a hold.
Aye, sir.
RIKER:
Freighter Sanction,
this is the Enterprise
get to your transporter...
No, forget about that.
Lock onto any life-form
you can find
and get them
over here now.
Trying, sir.
The freighter is going down.
Transporter room,
you're out of time.
Reading six life-forms,
but I can't get a solid lock.
We have no choice.
Energize.
I thought you said
there were six.
Where are the other two?
The lock didn't hold.
Reestablish.
It's too late.
Number One?
Two are lost, sir
but we saved four.
I'm Commander William Riker
of the USS Enterprise.
I'm sorry we were unable
to rescue the other two.
We did everything we could.
If you had come instead
of sending your cargo
you all would
have made it.
The cargo-- where is it?
You did save it, didn't you?
Yes, we did.
It's in one of our cargo holds.
You act as if
it's more important
than your comrades.
The cargo--
may we see it?
Follow me.
Thank you. Thank you.
We thought we had lost it.
Careful with your
choice of words, T'Jon.
It's ours, not yours.
We paid a fair
price for it.
You offered a fair price.
We have not received it.
You accepted our
goods in trade.
Then where are they, hmm?
Tell me.
That's not our problem.
No more than the barrel
is your property.
It's as simple as this--
the goods were
never delivered.
They were destroyed
with your ship.
Hence the deal
was incomplete
hence possession of
the felicium remains ours.
We need it.
Commander, I request
you transport
my associate and myself
down to Brekka
with our
merchandise.
T'JON:
Yes!
Get them out of here.
But the barrel stays.
There's no
reasoning with you.
Langor, you expect
too much from them.
You always have
and you've always
been disappointed.
You didn't pay for it.
Therefore,
it's not yours.
Damn you, Sobi.
Ah!
( grunting )
Stop this.
Now!
RIKER:
Security
to Cargo Bay 11.
Behave yourselves,
gentlemen.
Escort our visitors
to the observation lounge.
A natural
electrical charge?
Formidable.
Yes, and a difficult
weapon to confiscate.
I have never
seen humanoids
with that power.
Neither have I.
I wonder
how it evolved.
I wonder if the strong magnetic
field of their sun
might have something
to do with it.
Could be.
I wonder how much power
our guests can produce.
Or if they need
to recharge.
It's an interesting
ability.
The question is,
how do I defend
against it?
Do you think our visitors
pose a threat?
I don't know, but if
they do, I'd better
be ready for it.
Precisely, Lieutenant.
We have to resolve
this soon.
There isn't much time.
What can you offer?
Everything we had
went down with
the Sanction.
Then it's going
to be difficult
to accommodate you.
Solar flares increasing
in magnitude, Captain.
Shields are shaky,
but they're holding.
Maintain.
How are our rather
quarrelsome guests?
They're waiting for you
in the observation lounge, sir.
Data, what information
can you give us
about the inhabitants
of this system?
Not very much, sir.
The only recorded contact
with the Delos system
was over 200 years ago.
A scout ship reported
two inhabited planets--
one of which was on the verge
of acquiring space travel.
Ah, then, in two centuries,
neither civilization
advanced much further.
Sir, I find it strange
that none of our visitors
feels much remorse
about the two freighter
passengers who perished.
Yet that barrel of cargo
is a source of great
anxiety to them.
Mm-hmm, yes, let's pay a call,
get some answers.
Number One, Mr. Data.
Mr. La Forge,
you have the bridge.
Aye, sir.
Captain, may I present Sobi and
Langor from the planet Brekka
and T'Jon and Romas
from Ornara.
I'm sorry we couldn't
save your ship.
Tell me, you could
have repaired it?
PICARD:
Oh, yes.
We have only two left,
and neither works properly.
They are critical
to our survival.
Will you fix them?
Mr. Data?
Our computer has downloaded
the specifications
for the magnetic coils
the freighters depend on.
Assuming the malfunction
is similar
suitable
replacements
can be
fabricated.
Instruct Engineering
to proceed.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
Now, as for our cargo...
Our cargo, Captain.
Wrong, Sobi.
My First Officer has said
that ownership of this cargo
is in dispute,
but this question
must be settled
by whatever legal machinery
exists
between your two societies.
Captain, you
don't understand.
This is a matter
of life and death.
Why is that?
What is this cargo?
Medicine.
Indeed.
Our planet is
in desperate need, Captain.
We have people suffering
from a lethal plague.
T'JON:
The cargo
you have impounded
is the only hope
of life for our people.
Is that so?
Yes.
You must think us
heartless brutes, Captain
but look at
our side of it.
The plant which yields
the medicine felicium
grows only in remote
areas of Brekka.
It must be painstakingly
cultivated, harvested
purified-- a complex
and expensive process.
That single shipment
of felicium
represents an
enormous investment.
We can't just
give it away.
We paid for it.
We ask for only what is ours.
That is
your viewpoint.
Ours, of course, differs.
You are going to hold
to that position?
I am constrained to abide
by the terms of our agreement.
Then you condemn
us to death!
Romas...
You disgust me!
If you could see the suffering
the plague has caused.
Well, you are going to
when you see
what it does to us.
Romas, are you and T'Jon
carrying this plague?
Yes.
Every Ornaran does.
Then you may have
brought it aboard this ship.
Was there a medical scan
when they transported?
Unverified.
The solar flares could have
caused a malfunction
in the biofilter.
( sighing )
Med alert.
Medical emergency--
Dr. Crusher
to the observation
lounge at once.
You find us well,
I trust.
As far as I can tell.
Your physiology
is somewhat different
than I've ever encountered
but I detect no dangerous
virus or bacteria.
I assure you we're
in perfect health.
But we
are not.
We need
our medicine.
Our medicine.
We paid for it,
it's ours now.
Enough.
Of course.
You are right, Doctor.
Could we leave now?
I see no
reason why not.
Escort them
to their quarters.
Doctor.
Captain, could I speak
with you, please?
In private.
Not right now.
Captain.
What have you learned?
The Brekkians show
no sign of infection.
The Ornarans show all
the symptoms of a disease
but I can't
find a cause.
Perhaps it was filtered out
by the transporter
when they were beamed aboard.
There's no
record of it
then again, the solar
flare activity
might have caused
a malfunction
in the biofilters
or their monitors.
Are they going to die?
I need to check further,
but my instinct says no.
Do you think that we're in
any danger from this plague?
Again, I need
more time.
There are some missing
pieces to this puzzle.
What's missing is
a little compassion.
We're losing our professional
detachment, Doctor.
Perhaps.
But, Captain,
I must tell you
I am developing a
very active dislike
for these Brekkians.
Understandable.
Captain, you must
give us back our cargo.
I can't do that.
Why? It belongs to us.
The Brekkians claim
it belongs to them.
They lie.
That may be so but...
it is not
my decision.
We need some now.
Now.
I don't care if
it's your decision--
get us some.
Captain, what is
happening to us
is happening
to thousands
more on Ornara.
Please understand
the magnitude of the problem.
Your people
don't need it.
The Brekkians
Our people do.
If you don't give it to us,
you will be a party to murder--
not only of us
but of an entire
civilization.
I-I-I am sorry, I do not
mean to insult you.
I'm feeling very shaky.
We cannot hold out
much longer.
They believe it
will help them.
That in itself might
control their symptoms.
I'll talk
with the Brekkians.
We thank you, Captain.
We appreciate
anything you can do.
( door chimes )
May I say, Captain,
how impressed we are
with your ship
and all its facilities?
Thank you.
And its crew.
Everyone is so efficient
and professional.
I'm glad you're comfortable.
I've come to seek your agreement
to an Ornaran request.
We cannot agree.
Wait, let the Captain speak.
We want to be
reasonable.
The two Ornarans
are really quite ill
and are insisting that
they need the felicium.
That is not surprising.
Would you object
to giving them enough
for their own
immediate needs?
Captain, we Brekkians
are in business.
We are not in the habit
of giving away
that which has not
been paid for.
You would see them die,
rather than share the medicine?
LANGOR:
We want to be
fair, Captain.
We agree to permitting
them two doses
for immediate use.
No charge.
I'll let my medical
officer handle it.
Captain...
I trust you won't mind
if we're present
while you open the cargo.
What does that device do?
This measures
the individual portions.
What's the dosage?
.01 milliliters.
A very potent substance.
We've improved our distillation
process over the years.
In my grandfather's day,
this same amount of felicium
would have filled
five rooms this size.
But, now with our
improved processes
this one barrel contains
over 4,000,000,000 doses.
I would estimate
4 billion, 375 million...
Thank you, Mr. Data.
How long is
the dosage effective?
LANGOR:
It varies with
the individual.
But never more
than 72 hours.
And then the symptoms return?
Yes.
Unfortunately, there is
no cure for the plague.
But felicium inhibits the
sickness with total efficiency.
Allowing the Ornarans
to lead normal lives.
An unusual disease--
virulent, extremely persistent
yet I can't
isolate it.
The plague has
baffled doctors
on both planets
for 200 years.
We've therefore concentrated
on treatment--
finding new ways
to improve the potency
and purity
of felicium.
DATA:
No doubt you have
applied your technology
from other industries to the
refinement of this product.
We have no other industry.
None at all?
We don't
need any.
The Ornarans provide us
with everything we need
in exchange for this.
Fascinating.
Your society
dedicated exclusively
to the production
of a single product.
A product for which
you have no use
but which the Ornarans
cannot live without.
One of life's little ironies,
Captain.
But one would be fools
not to take advantage of.
It's mutually beneficial.
The Ornarans provide us
with the necessities of life
and we provide them
with the necessities of living.
It is a fair exchange.
Interesting
relationship.
Excuse me.
I'll take that
to Sick Bay.
BEVERLY:
Can I help?
No...
Hurry up.
You're feeling better?
Yes, thank you.
I'm fine now.
( door chimes )
Come.
Doctor?
I may not know
felicium's full effect
on Ornaran physiology
but I know
how to interpret
physical reactions.
Are the Ornarans recovering?
T'Jon and Romas
are feeling fine.
In fact, too fine.
Felicium's a narcotic.
Then T'Jon and Romas
and everyone on their world...
Is a drug addict.
I think you'll find
it's a fascinating tale
that we've come across
here, Captain.
You've piqued my interest,
Number One.
Please continue.
Data, what have we got?
Beginning several
thousand years ago
the two planets
took different paths.
Ornara became technologically
sophisticated.
Brekka did not.
Then,
200 years ago
Ornara was stricken
by a devastating plague.
Their advanced technology
could provide no solution.
Somehow, and there is limited
information on this point
a cure was found in a plant
indigenous
only to Brekka
and which rejected
all attempts at cultivation
on Ornara.
In any case,
a trading situation developed
which still
exists.
A nice arrangement
for the Brekkians.
And for the Ornarans.
Without the medicine,
they would all die.
No, they wouldn't.
Despite what the Ornarans
have been saying
it is not a medicine.
It was a medicine
but it cured the plague
200 years ago.
The plague is irrelevant now.
It doesn't exist.
Then why are they so desperate
for the felicium?
It's an addiction.
The physical
and psychological
need is very real.
Thank you.
What are you
going to do?
Based on what
we know so far
there's nothing I can do.
You don't think drug addiction
and exploitation
is sufficient cause
to do something?
This situation has existed
for a very long time.
These two societies
are intertwined
in a symbiotic relationship.
With one society
profiting at the expense
of the other.
That's how you see it.
I can synthesize
a non-addictive substitute
which will ease
their withdrawal symptoms.
No, I can't do that either.
You can't let them
have the felicium.
Why, because it offends
against our sensibilities?
It is not our mission to impose
Federation or Earth values
on any others in the galaxy.
Well, in this case, Captain,
I disagree 100 percent.
YAR:
Captain, I'm receiving a call
from Ornara.
The signal
is ragged,
but I think
I can put it
on the viewscreen.
PICARD:
Do it.
I'm Margan.
Are my people on board
your ship?
Some of them, yes.
May I speak to them?
Yes.
Lieutenant Yar, have
the Ornarans brought in.
No, wait.
I don't want them to have
access to the Bridge.
We will contact you
in a few minutes.
I will continue this
in the guest quarters.
Commander.
Doctor.
Data, I can understand
how this could happen
to the Ornarans.
What I can't understand
is why anyone
would voluntarily
become dependent
on a chemical.
DATA:
Voluntary
addiction to drugs
is a recurrent theme
in many cultures.
Wesley, no one wants
to become dependent.
That happens later.
But it does happen.
So why do people start?
On my home planet
there was so much poverty
and violence
that for some, the only escape
was through drugs.
How can a chemical substance
provide an escape?
It doesn't
but it makes you think
it does.
You have to understand
drugs can make you feel good.
They make you feel
on top of the world.
You're happy,
sure of yourself, in control.
But it's artificial.
It doesn't feel
artificial
until the drug
wears off.
Then you pay
the price.
Before you know it
you're taking the drug
not to feel good
but to keep from feeling bad.
And that's the trap.
All you care
about is getting
your next dosage.
Nothing else matters.
I guess I just don't understand.
Wesley, I hope you never do.
PICARD:
Lieutenant Yar, we're ready
in the guest quarters.
( static )
T'Jon?
Do you have it?
Yes, it is
here, but...
You've got to get it to us.
T'Jon, please.
We're dying down here.
You don't know, it's worse
than it's ever been before.
I'm doing
everything I can.
You see, what
happened was...
Stop!
I can't listen anymore!
T'Jon.
There's so many people here!
So much suffering.
We need the medicine.
You've got to get it to us!
I can't go on.
Help, T'Jon.
Please.
I'm sorry.
You will take us
to our planet
and leave us there
with our medicine or
this person dies.
Don't you see,
I have no choice.
We were sent to bring
the felicium back.
The suffering
on my planet
is too great.
People are dying.
It doesn't matter
whether we're
entitled to it or not.
We must have it.
Let him go.
You will take us
there now.
Or give us a shuttle
but we must have
the medicine.
If you refuse,
this person will die.
I will not be coerced.
I will do it.
I will kill him.
No.
No, you won't.
You're not a killer.
Help us, please.
Help us.
I'm not sure that I can.
My insides are
still shaking
but I'm
all right.
( door chimes )
Captain Picard,
could I see you a moment?
I'll stay here.
PICARD:
Come with me,
Doctor.
This could be
interesting.
LANGOR:
We have thought
about this a great deal.
We both feel deeply
about what is
happening on Ornara.
And although
it is going to cause
hardship to us
and to our people
we have decided to give
the felicium to them.
They can pay
whenever they are able.
We don't
want to be
the ones responsible
for their suffering.
There goes
the other shoe.
They know.
What do they know?
They know that the Ornarans
no longer have the plague.
They know
that felicium
is no longer
a medicine.
So, of course, they are willing
to give this shipment
because they don't want to take
the chance that the Ornarans
will lose
their addiction.
They don't want to lose
their only customers.
How would they have known
all of that
unless the plague had once
infected their planet, as well?
They were infected.
They used the felicium
to cure themselves
but, somehow, their ancestors
realized that it was a narcotic.
BEVERLY:
They broke the cycle
of addiction
and never told
the Ornarans?
They let them
continue to believe
that, without the felicium,
they would die?
PICARD:
I think it's worse
than that.
My guess
is that
this refining process,
of which you are so proud...
Is only to increase
the potency of the felicium
and tighten
your grip.
What are you going to do?
Are you going
to tell them?
No, I'm bound by the rules of
the United Federation of Planets
which order me not to interfere
with other worlds,
other cultures.
If I were to tell them
any of this
I would violate
that Prime Directive.
But you are talking to us
about it.
This is information
you already know
and so nothing
is changed.
If you can't interfere
then you are going to allow
the Ornarans to have
the felicium.
Yes, I am.
No, don't do it.
Jean-Luc,
this is not
a symbiotic
relationship.
This is exploitation--
pure and simple.
The Brekkians have
caused all of this
suffering and hardship
only to make their
pitiful lives easier.
And all of it
based on a lie.
No, deny them
this shipment.
It is the least
we can do.
From the moment they agreed
to give them the felicium
my hands were tied.
LANGOR:
You are absolutely
right, Captain.
It's not your business.
T'JON:
Are these
the spare parts
for our freighters?
They look
complicated.
Are they already...
Aligned?
Right.
You'd have to ask
the Captain.
LA FORGE:
Captain Picard,
we've arrived at Ornara
and assumed standard orbit.
Acknowledged.
Thank you.
Captain, please.
My planet
is suffering.
We beg you
to give us
our medicine.
The matter is already decided.
You're beaming down to your
world with the felicium.
Great.
( laughing )
I knew it.
I knew
you'd help us.
We thank you.
Don't thank me.
Sobi and Langor--
they decided
to let you
have it.
We'll discuss
the payment terms later.
In the meantime,
there's no reason
to deprive you
of your needed medicine.
That's terrific.
I'm sure
we can come
to a fair deal
for payment.
May we beam down with
you and discuss it?
Of course.
You are quite
welcome on Ornara.
We appreciate
your hospitality.
T'JON:
And Captain--
we appreciate
your gift of the coils.
Once our freighters
are fixed, everything
will be back
to normal.
No.
No?
The coils stay here.
What about
our freighters?
PICARD:
If you want
to repair them
you'll have to learn
to do it yourselves.
We can't.
If you don't help
us, our ships
will soon
be inoperable.
Quite possibly.
If you withhold those coils
you'll be disrupting the
stability of both our planets.
And interfering
with a trade agreement
that has lasted for generations.
What of your Prime Directive?
In this situation,
the Prime Directive
prohibits me from helping you.
That's absurd!
You did not think so
when it worked in your favor.
Do you want our world to suffer?
Oh no, I don't want that.
T'JON:
Without
the freighters
there will be no more shipments
of felicium.
We will die.
You must trust
yourselves.
There are...
other options.
Ensign, prepare
to beam our guests
and their cargo
down to Ornara.
Captain, I hope you realize
what you've done to us.
Of that, you can be sure.
Good luck.
Main bridge.
( beeping )
When the felicium
runs out
the people of Ornara
will suffer horrible
withdrawal pains.
No doubt,
but they will pass.
That seems so cruel.
We could have made
their burden easier.
Could have?
Perhaps
in the short term
but to what end?
Hold.
( beeping )
Beverly, the Prime Directive
is not just a set of rules.
It is a philosophy,
and a very correct one.
History has proved
again and again
that whenever mankind interferes
with a less-developed
civilization
no matter
how well
intentioned
that interference may be
the results
are invariably disastrous.
It's hard to be philosophical
when faced with suffering.
Believe me, Beverly, there was
only one decision.
I just hope
it was the right one.
And we may
never know.
Resume.
( beeping )
Mr. La Forge,
take us out of orbit.
Destination, sir?
I don't care.
Let's just get some distance
between us and this system.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
Course nine-seven-zero
mark three-one-eight.
Speed, warp three.
Where will that take us,
Mr. La Forge?
The Opperline system.
An interesting choice.
Why?
Curiosity.
We've never been there.
Engage.