PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41601.3.
We are crossing through
the Zed Lapis sector
where we will rendezvous
with Shuttlecraft 13
carrying Deanna Troi
who is returning
from a conference.
Because engineering is involved
in preventive maintenance
on our dilithium crystals
we are presently traveling
on impulse power.
Routine deep sensor probes
indicate no obstacles
or vessels within a range
of three light years.
Confirmed.
The martial arts competition
is in three days.
Are you prepared?
I will be if you'll meet me
on the holodeck later.
I need your help
with the Mishiama
wrist-lock and break.
If it works on you
I can use it
on anyone.
A valid assumption.
Who is your
first competitor?
Science Officer Swenson.
You will defeat him easily.
Well, I'm more concerned
with Lieutenant Minnerly's
kick-boxing.
You are favored
in the ship's pool.
You bet on me?
A sure thing.
LA FORGE:
Captain
estimated rendezvous
with the shuttle
in one hour and ten minutes.
Thank you,
Lieutenant.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
It'll be good to have
Counselor Troi back,
won't it, Number One?
It certainly will.
WORF:
Sir!
I'm receiving an emergency
transmission from the shuttle.
PICARD:
On main viewer.
I can't, sir.
We're receiving
audio only.
PICARD:
Open the frequency.
Aye, sir.
LIEUTENANT PRIETO:
What a jolt.
Position report?
Sir, I have an onboard
systems failure.
You'll have to tell me
where I am.
I read your coordinates
at three-seven-zero
point two-three-six.
Confirm.
PRIETO:
I can't confirm.
My instruments are haywire.
Lieutenant Prieto,
is Counselor Troi all right?
PRIETO:
Yes, sir.
Just a little shaken.
We're being buffeted a bit.
Losing more power!
My flight control
computer's fried.
Main engineering.
ENGINEERING:
Lieutenant Commander
Leland T. Lynch here, sir.
How long before we can return
to warp power?
Captain, I'm in the middle
of realigning
the dilithium crystals.
PICARD:
There is an emergency.
We need warp drive.
How long?
20 minutes--
maybe more.
We don't have it, Mr. Lynch.
LYNCH:
I'll align it by hand.
Whatever it takes.
LYNCH:
Aye, sir.
Shuttle, this is the Enterprise.
Your coordinates now read
two-three-seven
point one-zero-one.
Ben, you're dangerously close
to a planet.
PRIETO:
I can see it.
The planet is Vagra II, sir,
in the Zed Lapis sector.
Uninhabited.
Lieutenant, report.
This is Counselor Troi.
I'll relay, sir.
The pilot is busy.
We've lost most
of our impulse power.
Engineering, status report.
Working on it, Captain.
Three minutes.
But there are no guarantees.
PRIETO:
Captain, we're out of control.
We're caught
in the planet's gravity.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've lost all contact
with Shuttlecraft 13
and can only assume they've
crash-landed on Vagra II.
Meanwhile, main engineering
is trying
to return us to warp power.
Forget the final check.
Initiate start-up sequence.
COMPUTER:
Beginning checklist.
Override.
We're going directly
to start-up.
COMPUTER:
That procedure
is not recommended.
Understood. Now!
Prime matter/antimatter
injectors.
Set ratio
at 25 to one.
COMPUTER:
Ratio set.
Power engine core.
Inject reactants.
Leland T. Lynch here, Captain.
We now have minimum warp drive.
Course plotted and set
for Vagra II, sir.
Warp eight.
LYNCH:
I said, minimum warp drive,
Captain.
You heard the order, Mr. Lynch.
Make it so.
LYNCH:
Yes, sir.
LA FORGE:
Approaching
Vagra II, Captain.
Strange, sir.
There is no emergency signal
from the shuttle as yet.
What is this place, Mr. Data?
There is little information
in the library computer
other than the fact
of its existence.
Our sensors show
no signs of life-forms.
Virtually no vegetation.
Atmosphere?
DATA:
Minimum for
our needs, sir.
Standard orbit.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir,
standard orbit.
I've located
the shuttle.
Life signs?
WORF:
Not yet, sir.
Still probing.
It appears to be buried
under a lot of debris.
I may have something, sir.
Faint life signs.
Very faint.
How many?
There's no way
of telling from here.
Data, can we beam up
the injured?
No, sir.
Our sensors
are not fully penetrating
whatever the debris is.
That's very unusual.
DATA:
Yes, sir.
I cannot
explain.
Number One,
prepare your away team.
Right away.
Data!
Yar!
Dr. Crusher, have you been
monitoring all this?
BEVERLY:
Yes, I'll meet the away team
in Transporter Room Four.
BEVERLY:
Let's go.
The life signs
are weak.
RIKER:
What is this?
No idea.
We'll go around just to
be on the safe side.
Let's try
the other way.
Enterprise, this is Riker.
We've got a problem.
What kind of problem,
Number One?
RIKER:
I'm not sure yet.
There appears to be some kind
of a slick blocking our path.
We'll keep you apprised.
Maintain an open frequency.
RIKER:
Aye, sir.
Analysis, Mr. Data.
Inconclusive, sir.
I cannot tell you
what it is
but I can tell you
what it is not.
Explain.
There is no evidence
of neural
or circulatory systems.
No internal
organs.
Cellular structure,
unknown.
Does not have any proteins
which are known to us.
It's narrower over here.
We can get over it.
How is it moving, Data?
I do not
know, sir.
It does not
appear to have
a skeletal framework
or musculature.
Then what's causing it to move?
It appears
to be following us, sir.
No sign
of intelligence--
no brain as we know it--
yet evidence of thought,
Mr. Data?
Insufficient information, sir.
Is it a life-form, Data?
DATA:
Again, insufficient
information, sir.
Theorize.
It is possible.
( rumbling growls )
( deep male voice ):
Very good, tin man.
What is it, Number One?
What are you seeing?
Trouble.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
While on a mission
to rescue survivors
from an unexplained
shuttle crash
the away team has encountered
a strange creature
which seems able to assume
different forms
including one
which resembles humanoid.
PICARD:
Easy, Number One.
Let's find out what it is
we're dealing with.
RIKER:
Agreed, Captain.
And, Number One, I don't believe
that the location of the crash
and the proximity
of the creature
is a coincidence.
I'm Commander William Riker
of the USS Enterprise.
I am Armus.
Why are you here?
We mean you no harm.
We have injured crewmen
in the shuttlecraft.
We need to get to them.
May we pass?
You haven't given me
a good enough reason.
Preserving life, all life,
is very important to us.
Why?
We believe everything
in the universe
has a right to exist.
An interesting notion
which I do not share.
You may leave
now if you wish.
We are not going
without our shuttle crew.
I warn you.
YAR:
Enough.
We have people
who need attention.
We won't hurt you
but we must help them.
PICARD:
Number One?
The creature attacked us.
Lieutenant Yar is down.
It seems to feed
on our phaser energy.
We had no effect
on it.
PICARD:
What's Lieutenant Yar's
condition?
( instrument beeping rapidly)
PICARD:
Doctor Crusher, report.
She's dead.
Transporter room.
Get them up, now!
I need her in Sick Bay now.
Go to yellow alert,
Lieutenant Worf.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
Aye, sir.
Status, Doctor?
Unchanged.
Can you bring her back?
BEVERLY:
We'll see.
Neural
stimulator.
NURSE:
Neural stimulator
locked in.
BEVERLY:
Interlock
current feeds.
Set sensitivity factor to 4.4.
NURSE:
Affirmative.
TECHNICIAN:
Monitoring 2.3, 1.8.
There, you did it.
No, I've got her
on total support.
There is no independent
brain functioning.
TECHNICIAN:
Current feeds operating.
NURSE:
She's not
responding, Doctor.
Her synaptic network
is breaking down.
Inject norep.
NURSE:
Neurons are beginning
to depolarize.
Let's go for direct
reticular stimulation.
Direct?
Do it.
( electronic zap )
Increase to 70 microvolts.
85 microvolts.
( electronic zap )
Again.
( whispering ):
90.
( electronic zap )
BEVERLY:
Again.
( electronic zap )
BEVERLY:
Again.
( electronic zap )
She's gone.
Gone?
There was too much
synaptic damage.
That thing just sucked
the life right out of her.
There's nothing I can do.
( communicator not functioning)
( suction noises )
ARMUS:
Your friends
have deserted you.
They're not coming back.
You're wrong.
I killed one of them.
Yes.
I know.
How could you
be in there
and know that?
I felt her die.
Do you want
to know why
I killed her?
Your answer would be
meaningless.
That act had no reason.
Exactly.
It had no meaning.
I did it
because I wanted to.
It amused me.
No, you thought it would
amuse you, but it didn't.
You felt no satisfaction.
No, it was too easy.
You wanted her to suffer.
You have a great need.
I need nothing.
Liar.
End this.
Let us go.
Not yet.
They won't give you
what you want.
And what is that?
To break their spirit.
Oh, is that
what I want?
If breaking their spirit
will amuse me
then that's
what I will have.
Never.
She didn't do anything.
Her phaser was lowered.
LA FORGE:
She only wanted to get to
Troi and Lieutenant Prieto.
RIKER:
There was nothing at all
provocative about what she did.
BEVERLY:
It was a brutal,
senseless act.
Lieutenant Yar's death is
very painful for all of us.
We will have to deal with it
as best we can for now.
Until the shuttle crew is
safely beamed aboard this ship
our feelings will have to wait.
Is that understood?
Lieutenant Worf
you are now acting
Chief of Security.
I will do
my best, sir.
Doctor, what is the state
of the shuttle crew?
We're still receiving
faint life signs
but the sensor readings
are fluctuating.
They may not
be accurate.
Armus is capable of creating
undefined force fields.
In effect, we are powerless
to communicate
or use the transporter
unless it allows it.
A creature against whom
we seem to have no defense.
Number One?
It's down on that planet
waiting for us to come back.
It killed Tasha
and it could have killed us,
but it didn't.
Deanna and Ben are alive
for a reason.
And it knows that we're
not going anywhere
as long as they're
still alive.
Are you saying that its attack
on Yar was not arbitrary
but part of some tactic?
The only way to find out
is to go back down.
Commander, I may be able to see
something in the creature
which might be helpful.
Agreed.
Prepare your away team,
Number One.
Lieutenant Worf?
I will remain
on the ship.
WORF:
The object here
is not to engage
the creature
in battle.
The goal
is the safe return
of Counselor Troi
and Lieutenant Prieto.
I can best accomplish this
at the tactical station.
Very good.
Number One.
Enterprise.
PICARD:
Number One.
We're approaching
the shuttlecraft.
The creature
is covering it.
ARMUS:
I lied to you.
They came back.
Let me talk with them.
No.
Why?
Does the thought
of my having contact with them
make you uneasy?
No, not being able
to contact you--
not knowing
if you are alive--
makes them uneasy.
Can't you feel
how worried they are?
Yes.
Yes, they are worried.
They care for you.
You must be
very special.
We are members of a community.
We all care for one another.
Equally?
You were really surprised
they came back.
Yes.
Why?
Because the others did not?
What others?
You can't hide
the emptiness from me.
The others.
The ones who hurt you.
Who left you alone, rejected.
The ones who make you so angry.
What do you
know of them?
Only what you tell me.
I will tell you
nothing.
Not now...
but soon.
Captain, look at this.
The force
of the energy field
around the shuttlecraft
decreased for a few moments
when the creature
was draped over it.
PICARD:
But not low enough
to beam them out.
Almost.
It's approaching
the away team now
and the energy field
over the shuttlecraft
is back to
full intensity.
Chart it.
I want to see
if there's a pattern.
Aye, sir.
She said you'd be back.
Then she is alive.
For now.
Why have you
returned?
We have no choice.
We're here to negotiate
for our team.
What do you want?
Maybe I want nothing.
RIKER:
Then you would
have killed all of us.
Armus:
I still might.
RIKER:
What do you want?
Tell me.
Maybe we can reach
an accommodation.
If I tell you, will
you give it to me?
I might.
It depends.
I am a doctor.
I need to treat
our injured friends.
Say, "please."
Please.
You ask nicely.
I will allow it.
Wait!
I've changed my mind.
Talk to her
from here.
How...
Troi, can you hear me?
BEVERLY:
Deanna, are you all right?
Beverly?
TROI:
I can hear you.
Are you all right?
Yes.
We've encountered
some difficulty.
I know.
She needs our help.
So what?
Our friends are suffering
a few meters away
yet you block our path.
Why?
You are all ungrateful.
BEVERLY:
What is he
made of?
DATA:
It did not register
on the tricorder.
"It?" Does that mean
I am not alive?
No, clearly you
are some kind
of intelligent form.
But you said
I did not register
on your instrument.
Perhaps your instruments
are useless.
Don't help him.
Data.
Half meter
to the right, Geordi.
Aren't you going
to lead him
to his sight again, robot?
No, you will just move it again
and I will not help you
hurt him.
Then give it to him.
I will find
something else
to amuse me.
You said they
wouldn't amuse me.
You were right.
And the emptiness remains.
You sound so alone.
I am alone.
Abandoned.
Who deserted you?
Creatures whose beauty
now dazzles all who see them.
They would not exist
without me.
You were together.
They perfected a means
of bringing to the surface
all that was evil
and negative within...
erupting, spreading,
connecting.
In time, it formed
a second skin--
dank and vile.
You.
Yes.
They discarded you and left.
And here I am.
You have my pity.
( rumbling growls )
Your pity?
Save that for yourself!
( no audio )
Data!
Data, something's got me!
ARMUS:
Touch him, and he dies.
No!
No, don't!
Enterprise.
Armus has... enveloped
Commander Riker.
I'm beaming you up.
If any of you leave now,
he dies.
And so do the survivors
of the crash.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
There is grave danger
to the crew on Vagra II.
My first officer is missing--
attacked by this entity
known as Armus.
Captain, perhaps you
should take a look at this.
WORF:
We have the chart
of the energy field
surrounding the shuttle.
There are a lot
of fluctuations.
Yes, but there is
a pattern.
Here is where it killed
Lieutenant Yar
and here is where it
absorbed Commander Riker.
And here, here, where
the energy is lowest?
Both times, it had
enveloped the shuttle.
It has something to do
with Counselor Troi.
PICARD:
Somehow, when it's
dealing with her
the energy field
is affected.
I want to talk to her.
I'm going to beam down.
Lieutenant Worf,
you have the conn.
TROI:
Imzadi!
No, please stop hurting him.
ARMUS:
He resists.
If he would give himself over,
the pain would diminish.
He struggles.
You should feel
his strength.
I can.
Should I let him go?
You only ask to torment me.
Perhaps.
How should I answer?
What can I offer except myself?
And would you give
yourself for him?
Would you give
that much?
Yes, without hesitation.
Just for him?
No, not just for him.
I would do the same
for any of the others.
Armus, you have me.
Let them go.
Perhaps...
Ah, another has arrived.
You are the one in charge?
Is Commander Riker alive?
Answer, tin man.
I would guess that death
is no longer sufficient
to alleviate
its boredom.
Therefore, Commander
Riker is alive.
Maybe.
Don't you want to ask me
what I want?
No.
Not even to protect
your own existence?
I want to see my people
in the shuttle.
Entertain me.
Hm-mm.
Then I will do it myself.
You, tin man--
Now, tell me,
how would you feel
if you were
the instrument
of death
for your leader?
Don't struggle, Data.
I have no control over
what you do with the phaser.
Therefore, I would not be
the instrument of his death.
Perhaps killing the doctor
would engender
more feeling.
No, the control
is still yours.
And what about
you, Doctor?
Are you ready to die?
Tell me you are
not afraid.
I am afraid.
Beg me to
spare you.
No.
One of you is going to die.
And you, Doctor, get to choose.
You don't like that,
do you?
Then I choose myself.
No.
You are going to live.
One of them dies.
Maybe this one.
Though I would not
call it death
since he is only a device.
Tell me,
tin man
how does
it feel
to face your
own extinction?
Curious.
( phaser drops to the ground)
You are capable
of great sadism and cruelty.
Interesting--
no redeeming qualities.
So what do you think?
I think you should be destroyed.
A moral judgment
from a machine?
Data.
Armus, we are finished
dealing with you.
I have your man in here
and the others in the shuttle.
It doesn't matter.
We will no longer be
a source of amusement.
I can kill them.
Yes, you can
but only I can command them.
They follow my orders.
Have them amuse me.
Only if you will let me see
my people on the shuttle first.
I must see them.
Not possible.
Then our business with you
is concluded.
And you claim you care
about your comrades.
I care.
Which is why
I must see them.
You want to see your people?
Then here.
Look...
at this one.
BEVERLY:
He's alive.
( gulping and gasping )
Don't move.
PICARD:
Is he
all right?
All signs
show normal.
RIKER:
So much
frustration
it had to get
rid of me.
Now, let me see the others.
No.
I will not allow my people
to entertain you until you do.
They are incapable
of entertaining me.
PICARD:
I want the four
of you out of here.
Enterprise, beam
up the away team
immediately.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
( sighs )
They're no longer involved.
This is between you and me.
They may leave.
Now...
I want to leave
this place.
You want me to give
you transportation?
For which
I will trade you lives.
I must see my people
in the shuttle.
Will you give me
what I want?
I have the means
but, first,
I must see my people.
If you must.
Troi, are you
all right?
Yes, but Ben
is not.
He's alive.
Were you able to help Tasha?
No.
Troi...
Troi, we must talk.
I believe
it's possible
to outmaneuver
this creature
and beam you and Ben
back up to the ship.
We've been monitoring
the energy field
that surrounds the shuttle.
When the creature is here,
the field weakens.
Do you know why?
The creature
is filled with rage--
undirected, unfocused rage.
When he confronts it,
his guard goes down
because he's feeling it
instead of suppressing it.
Acknowledging his needs
makes him
vulnerable.
What caused the rage?
He was left here--
abandoned.
WORF:
The force field
will have to drop
below 2.7 before
we can beam them up.
Satisfied?
Yes.
Then, can we leave?
Where do you
want to go?
Do you want to try to find
those who left you here?
She told you
about them!
How long have
you been here?
Since they left--
a very long time.
A long time to be alone.
Save your
compassion.
It's revolting.
You offer it like a prize
when, in fact, it's an insult.
Because you feel unworthy.
You overrate
your gift.
You humans are puny--
weak.
But our spirit is indomitable.
And still, you die
from a flick of my power.
A great poet once said
"All spirits are enslaved
that serve things evil."
You do not understand.
I do not serve things evil--
I am evil.
Oh, no, you are not.
I am a skin of evil
left here by a race
of titans who believed
if they rid themselves of me,
they would free
the bonds of
destructiveness.
Yes, so here you are.
Feeding on your own loneliness,
consumed by your own pain
believing
your own lies.
Set the computer.
When the energy level
reaches 2.6.205
automatically beam up
Troi and Prieto.
We'll do a parallel
transport on the captain.
Yes, sir.
You say you
are true evil?
Shall I tell you
what true evil is?
It is to submit
to you.
It's when
we surrender
our freedom--
our dignity--
instead of defying you.
I will kill you
and those in there!
But you will still be here...
in this place.
Forever.
Alone.
Immortal.
( gasping and growling )
WORF:
Stand by for
parallel transport.
The energy level
has dropped to 2.6.3.
That's your real fear--
never to die.
Never again to be united
with those who left you here.
( gasping roar )
WORF:
Energy field
is 2.6.
Computer
beginning
transport.
( gasping )
I'm not taking you anywhere.
( wailing and screaming )
PICARD:
Captain's Log, Stardate 41602.1
The shuttlecraft
has been destroyed
to prevent any possibility
of Armus leaving the planet.
Vagra II will be
declared off-limits
but the damage has been done.
One of the saddest duties
I've ever had to perform
is now ahead of me.
We're here together to honor
our friend and comrade--
Lieutenant
Natasha Yar.
Coming to terms
with the loss
of a colleague
is perhaps the
most difficult
task we must face
in the work we have
chosen to pursue.
We will all
find time
to grieve for her in
the days that are ahead
but, for now,
she has asked
that we celebrate
her life... with this.
Hello, my friends.
You are here now watching this
image of me because I have died.
It probably happened
while I was on duty...
and quickly,
which is what I expected.
Never forget I died doing
exactly
what I chose to do.
What I want you to
know is how much
I loved my life
and those of you
who shared it with me.
You are my family.
You all know
where I came from
and what my life
was like before.
But Starfleet took that
frightened angry, young girl
and tempered her.
I have been blessed
with your friendship
and your love.
Will Riker--
you are the best.
You trusted me
you encouraged me
and most of all,
you made me laugh.
Deanna, you are capable
of so much love.
You taught me without
ever having to say a word.
I realized I could be feminine
without losing anything.
Ah, Worf...
we are so
much alike,
you and I--
both warriors--
orphans who found ourselves
this family.
I hope I met death
with my eyes
wide open.
Beverly, your
fierce devotion
comes from within.
It can't
be diminished.
From you, I have learned
to strive for excellence
no matter
what the personal cost.
Wesley, I'm sorry
I won't be able
to see you grow
into the exceptional
man you'll become.
But your kindness
and innocence are ageless.
Geordi...
in those moments
I felt the most despair
you took my hand
and helped me to see
things differently.
You taught me
to look beyond
the moment.
My friend, Data--
you see things
with the wonder
of a child.
And that makes you more human
than any of us.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
I wish I could say you've
been like a father to me
but I've never had one
so I don't know
what it feels like.
But if there were someone
in this universe
I could choose to be like--
someone who I would want
to make proud of me--
it's you.
You who have the heart
of an explorer
and the soul
of a poet.
So, you'll
understand
when I say
"death is that state
"in which one exists only
in the memory of others...
which is why it is not an end."
No good-byes.
Just good
memories.
Hailing frequencies
closed, sir.
Au revoir, Natasha.
The gathering is concluded.
Sir...
the purpose
of this gathering...
confuses me.
Oh? How so?
My thoughts
are not for Tasha
but for myself.
I keep thinking
how empty it will be
without her presence.
Did I miss
the point?
No, you didn't,
Data--
you got it.