Captain's Log,
Stardate 41697.9.
We're en route to Sarona VIII
for much-needed shore leave.
The entire crew is looking
forward to the diversion.
On a personal note
I have allowed myself
the luxury of a head start.
( beeping )
I took advantage.
No, no, Lieutenant.
The advantage was yours.
Come again.
En garde.
( beeping )
Interesting move, sir.
What technique
was that?
The technique
of a desperate man.
Interesting move,
sir.
What technique
was that?
The technique
of a desperate man.
Captain...
what was that?
Picard to Bridge.
RIKER:
Captain.
Number One,
did something unusual
just occur
on the Bridge?
Yes, sir. We experienced
some kind of loop
where everything
repeats itself.
Here, too.
I'm on my way.
Report, Mr. Data.
Sensors show nothing, sir
but it appears
a moment in time
repeated itself
exactly.
For everyone.
It was like a feeling
of deja vu.
Reports coming in
from all decks, sir.
Computers were
also affected, sir
which would indicate
the phenomenon was
not an illusion
but occurred
in real time.
Number One
find out if anything
similar happened
in this sector.
Sir, I am receiving
an emergency transmission
from the Pegos Minor System.
Put it on.
...542.2.
I repeat, this is
Dr. Paul Manheim.
We are in need of help.
Urgent. All ships,
please respond.
I repeat,
coordinates are 66728.9
by 7075...
It is an automated signal, sir.
I am unable
to establish contact.
This is Dr. Paul Manheim.
Shut it off.
Mr. La Forge, lay in a course
on those coordinates.
Aye, sir.
Captain, you act
as if there's a connection
between the time distortion
and the distress
signal.
There is.
Paul Manheim.
15 years ago, he went off
to work on experiments
relating to
non-linear time.
It appears he may
have achieved
some measure
of success.
Speed, warp 8.
Aye, sir.
Warp 8.
Engage.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Estimated arrival,
Pegos Minor--
four hours, 35 minutes,
17 seconds.
I've never heard
of Paul Manheim.
Mr. Data.
A highly respected scientist,
considered a visionary.
He advanced several
time-related theories.
One regarding the relationships
between time and gravity
was quite intriguing.
But neither that theory, nor any
other, received wide acceptance.
15 years ago, he assembled
a team of scientists
to expand that research.
They disappeared.
Haven't been heard from since.
Did you know him,
Captain?
I knew of him.
He was teaching at the
university when I was in Paris
but I, um...
didn't have the pleasure.
I must change.
Number One, inform me
half an hour
before we reach
those coordinates
and keep trying to determine
if the time distortion
was specifically located
on the Enterprise.
Yes, sir.
Captain.
Excuse me.
Yes, what is it,
Counselor?
I think you would prefer
to discuss this in private.
No, that's not necessary.
Go on.
When Professor Manheim's
name was mentioned
you reacted with
intense emotion.
Yes. Please, get
to the point.
I don't want to interfere
with your personal life
but unresolved, strong emotion
can affect judgment.
Well, thank you
for your concern.
As Ship's Counselor,
I offer my assistance.
What do you suggest?
Confronting deep personal
issues is not easy for you.
You tend to suppress them.
There are a few hours
until we arrive.
Perhaps you should use this
time to analyze your feelings
and put them
into perspective.
Thank you, Counselor.
If I should need you further,
I'll let you know.
Bridge.
Belay that.
Computer, estimated arrival
at Pegos Minor?
COMPUTER:
Two hours, nine minutes.
Holodeck Three.
Computer,
this is Captain Picard.
Holodeck Three is clear.
Location: Paris.
Cafe des Artistes
as it appeared...
22 years ago.
April the 9th, 1500 hours...
3:00.
Warm spring day.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
Monsieur, welcome
to the Cafe des Artistes.
Is this your first time
in Paris?
No.
This way.
That table.
Oh, mais bien sur, Monsieur.
We are here to please you.
I've been away
far too long.
Some wine?
Some cheese?
I'm not very hungry.
I really came
for the view.
Perhaps what you hunger
for is not on the menu.
Perhaps not.
It was many years ago.
I had a rendezvous.
I was to meet
someone...
someone here,
at that very table.
Your young lady,
she did not come?
Actually, I don't know.
I always imagined that she did.
You, however, did not.
Ah.
Well, trust Edouard.
I will bring something
very special, just for you.
Let's go, huh?
We've waited long enough.
Fran, you go.
I'll stay a little longer.
He's not coming,
Gabrielle.
No. After last night,
I know he will.
I just know it.
Then he would
be here.
You're making a fool
out of yourself
and I will
not watch.
Do we know each other?
No.
The way you look at me--
do I remind you of someone?
No.
Yes, you do somewhat.
He's not coming.
Why?
What did I do to drive him away?
Maybe you did nothing.
Maybe he had no choice.
Maybe he was afraid.
Of what? Of me?
Oh, of being connected.
Rooted.
Perhaps, if he's
as young as you are
he doesn't know yet exactly
what it is he wants to do.
Maybe...
Enough of this self-indulgence.
Exit.
Captain, we've
received communication
from the Freighter Lalo
as well as from a farming colony
on Coltar IV.
Both described the
same time distortion.
The Captain of the Lalo
described it as a hiccup.
Hiccup?
Actually, sir, that may
be an incorrect analogy.
How so, Data?
A hiccup
is a spasmodic inhalation
with closure of the glottis
accompanied by
a peculiar sound.
If we were to continue this
analogy to a body-function
what occurred would be
best represented by a...
Enough, Data.
Have you been able to learn
any more specifics
about the Manheim
project?
All I have found, sir,
is what you already know.
Manheim was concentrating
on time gravity experiments
when he left.
LA FORGE:
Captain.
We've reached the coordinates
specified.
There's nothing here.
I'm receiving
new coordinates.
It's a relay signal, same
source as the first one.
What are
they, Worf?
664.8 by 1323.7 by 4949.9.
Very remote area, sir.
It's in the middle
of the Vandor System
a binary star system.
Main star is a B-class giant.
The companion star
is a pulsar.
Set course for the new
coordinates, Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Why is he making it this
difficult to find him?
Hopefully, he'll
tell us, Number One.
We have reached the
coordinates, Captain.
Sensors indicate
it is Vandor IV--
a planetoid
in elliptical orbit
around the
binary system.
Standard orbit, Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Give me a visual.
Viewscreen on.
WORF:
There's a small
force field on the planet.
Latitude 20 degrees,
nine minutes north.
Longitude 40 degrees,
two minutes east
of the present terminator.
Penetrable?
No, sir.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies
open, sir.
This is Captain...
This is the Captain
of the USS Enterprise
responding to your
call for help.
WOMAN:
Enterprise.
Thank you for hearing us.
Where are you?
We're in orbit
around Vandor, now.
Then you can help me.
I-I don't know what to do.
It's only the two of us left.
He's having convulsions.
Please.
Can you lock on
to her coordinates?
No, sir. The force field is
preventing any kind of contact
other than audio.
There is a force field
at your location.
Yes, I know.
Good.
But it is preventing us
from helping you.
Now, you must try to find
some way to shut it down.
I'll try.
Force field is off.
Good.
Lock on to their coordinates.
Beam them up
directly to Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher, prepare
for a medical emergency.
Two to beam directly
up to Sick Bay.
CRUSHER:
We'll be ready, Captain.
That's where I'll be.
Number One.
Mr. Data.
I'll help.
Easy. Easy.
I've got his legs.
How long has he been like this?
Several hours,
at least.
He was in his lab,
so I can't be sure.
I need to do some tests.
I... uh...
Jean-Luc.
I thought the voice
sounded familiar.
Hello.
I should have known.
Who else would have
charged to my rescue?
This is my First Officer,
Commander William Riker.
Lieutenant Commander Data.
This is Jenice...
Manheim.
A pleasure, Mrs. Manheim.
Thank you.
I have a number
of questions for you.
I hope I can be
of some help.
Why don't we sit down in here?
You said that there were
only two of you left.
What happened
to the rest of the crew?
They were working
at the second lab.
Something happened there
a few weeks ago.
They were all killed.
It was a terrible accident.
I don't know
exactly what happened.
So many brilliant,
wonderful minds...
just gone.
Do you know the nature
of Dr. Manheim's work?
Paul's always been
interested in time.
He's never believed
that it was immutable
any more than space
is immutable.
Over the last decade,
he came to believe
that we reside in one
of infinite dimensions
and what holds
us here
is the constancy
of time.
Change that and it would be
what he called
opening the window
to those other dimensions.
Which begins
to explain what happened.
Have you been experiencing
something up here?
Yes, what is emanating here
is having repercussions
light years away
maybe even further.
That would explain his anxiety.
I had no idea it had gone
so far beyond Vandor.
Why this place?
Why Vandor?
All I can tell you about that
is that Paul
and the rest of the team
searched for two years
to find it.
Vandor is exactly
what they needed--
a planetoid
around a binary star.
Because of the dense
gravity of the pulsar.
Did your husband ever attempt
to define these dimensions
to give you an idea
of what
he expected?
No, but he did say
that he was very close
to proving his theories.
And then the accident...
Did he anticipate that these
experiments might be dangerous?
I didn't think so
but, now in retrospect,
he probably did.
That would explain
the unusual precautions
he began taking
even before the accident--
the force field
the elaborate
security system.
And every time he started
a new experiment
he insisted that I stay
in what he called
a protected room.
Aha, and that's why you
weren't affected.
Jean-Luc, he would never
knowingly do anything
to hurt anyone.
Yes, I believe that.
But as he saw his goal
getting closer--
seeming possible--
he became more
and more obsessive.
Maybe that clouded
his judgment.
This is not how I imagined
seeing you again.
Nor I you.
You've
done well.
A great starship
on the far reaches
of the galaxy.
It's everything you'd hoped.
( chuckling )
Not exactly.
Nothing works
just as you hope.
If you can't tell us
any more
I need to send
a team down to the lab.
You can't--
it's protected.
One of the young
scientists
made sure no one
could get in.
CRUSHER:
Uh, excuse me.
Is he worse?
He's resting.
But I'd like you
to undergo
some tests yourself.
My nurse will
start them.
Thank you
for your kindness, Doctor.
She's an old friend.
I gathered that.
It's her husband I'm more
concerned with at the moment.
What's the prognosis?
I believe
he's dying.
His neurochemistry
has been affected
but I don't know how or why.
I've never encountered
anything like it before.
How long does he have?
Maybe a couple
of days.
It's hard to predict.
All I can do
is maintain him--
or attempt
to maintain him--
until I find out
what's causing the damage.
Can we talk
to him?
Not now,
not yet.
Incidentally, Captain
the effects
of the time distortions
are now being felt
in the Ilecom System.
Bridge.
( beeping )
In the past decade
Manheim has turned
some vague theories
into a practical
application.
Yes, but without his help
I'm not sure we'll be able
to pose any
intelligent questions
let alone come up
with any solutions.
Incidentally, Captain
the effects
of the time distortions
are now being felt
in the Ilecom System.
It's us, before we stepped
into the turbolift.
It's happening again.
I feel no disorientation.
Nor do I.
What was that?
I believe what
could be termed as
the Manheim effect
is becoming
more pronounced.
This is where
we started.
If we are us.
Oh, we are us, sir
but they
are also us
so, indeed,
we are both us...
at different points
along the same time continuum.
Bridge.
( beeping )
What have
you learned?
We have completed a scan
of the planet's surface, sir.
We've discovered
the second lab.
It's on the far side
of the planet--
completely destroyed.
Unable to determine
what caused it.
Otherwise, very little
to clarify this situation.
Our sensors show
an immense volume of energy
emanating deep
within the planet
and concentrated near
Manheim's remaining laboratory.
How is the energy being used?
No idea.
What's its
source?
I cannot be sure, sir
but I believe Manheim
has developed a method
for harnessing energy
from the pulsar.
RIKER:
It comes down
to this, Captain--
we've learned everything
we can from here
and we are no closer
to understanding it
than we were 12 hours ago.
Manheim is unable to help us
but, hopefully, having been a
good scientist, he kept notes.
I would need to study
Manheim's records, sir.
In order to do that
we're going to have
to go down there.
What about the defense system
Mrs. Manheim spoke of?
It may have been connected
to the main system
and when she lowered
the shields
she may have turned
that off, as well.
If not, we'll deal with it
as best we can.
Prepare your team.
Aye, sir.
Coordinates set?
Yes, sir.
Energize.
There's a lack of integrity
at the landing point.
I'm losing them.
Bring them back-- now!
Chief Herbert,
what's going on?
There seems to be some kind
of strange bouncing effect.
I can't get them to materialize.
My readings aren't complete.
Keep trying.
What are we
doing back here?
You're lucky you made it back
at all, sir.
Where am I?
Paul?
Thank God.
You're on the
USS Enterprise.
They answered
your distress signal.
I sent one?
Oh Paul, you're going to be
just fine.
No, I am not fine, Jenice.
I'm not even close to fine.
Bridge, this is Dr. Crusher.
Professor Manheim is conscious.
MANHEIM:
Remember, it was worth it.
What happened, what
will happen, all of it.
It was all worth it.
Again.
It's changing again.
What is?
What do you see?
I am having difficulty.
With what?
Are you in pain?
I have been on the other side.
I have touched
another dimension.
Part of me
is still there.
Help him.
Try to stay calm, Dr. Manheim.
I don't think it's going to help
you, struggling against it.
My mind is floating
between two places.
It is difficult to know
which is which.
There is no way
to explain it.
Dr. Manheim,
I'm Captain Picard.
The same one?
She has told me about you.
Not all, but enough.
We need your help.
The situation is not good.
It will get worse.
What do we do?
How do we stop it?
I am having difficulty
holding the moment.
Doctor, this is Lieutenant
Commander Data.
Will you explain
the situation to him?
I am fully versed, sir,
on all your theories
regarding time and gravity.
How is that possible?
I am not even fully versed
on all my theories.
I am an android.
Android?
On a Starfleet vessel?
I am the only one, sir.
Your knowledge
is useless
because the work
we have done here
has made most
of those theories obsolete.
Then you have harnessed
a dynamic energy source.
Then you do
understand, yes.
We were able to locate
an energy source
in the center of this planetoid.
We learned to enhance it,
to focus it.
Everything worked too well.
The energy from the pulsar.
The energy from the planetoid.
We opened a crack...
a window into another dimension.
The time distortion we felt.
Felt?
Then it is not confined
to the planetoid?
The range is at least
several thousand
light years.
Captain, it must be stopped.
You must help me to execute
a controlled shut-down
of this experiment.
Get my notes.
They are in the lab.
How do we bypass
the security system?
I'll give you
the correct coordinates
to beam safely down to Vandor
and the codes you need
to bypass security systems
to get into my lab.
( gasps )
If what the professor
has given me is accurate
it is possible
to repair the damage
but it must be perfectly
timed to coincide
with another time
distortion episode.
Can we predict the timing?
I believe so, sir.
We have to.
If we don't seal that hole,
this other dimension he's opened
will rip into the fabric
of the galaxy.
Reality as we perceive it
will not be the same.
Lieutenant Worf.
Yes, sir?
I want those codes that
Manheim gave Mr. Data rechecked
and then checked again.
No one is beaming down to Vandor
unless we can be reasonably sure
they can get through.
Aye, sir.
I'm sorry for intruding.
I was told
I'd find you here.
You're not intruding.
We're just finished.
Come in.
Thank you.
I knew you wouldn't come to me.
No, not
under these circumstances.
We have unfinished business.
Yes, we do.
Why didn't you come to meet me
that last day in Paris?
I was afraid.
I didn't want this.
What?
The truth.
Oh, you want me to lie?
Of course.
A nice, soft, painless lie.
Oh, I got the days confused.
I thought it was Tuesday
when it was Wednesday.
I went to the Cafe Moulin
instead
of the Cafe des Artistes.
Ah, that's better.
It was raining
and you couldn't find a cab.
Mm-hmm.
I waited all day.
And it was raining.
It rained the rest of the week.
I went to Starfleet
Headquarters
looking for you
but you'd already
shipped out.
So, come on, Jean-Luc.
Let's hear the truth.
It was fear.
Fear of seeing you,
losing my resolve.
Fear of staying.
Losing myself.
Fear that neither
of these choices was right
and that either would have...
For a long time,
not a day went by
that I didn't look up
into the sky
and wonder.
Each time that I
returned to Earth
my thoughts were
filled with you.
I've thought a lot about this
over the years.
And perhaps you're leaving out
your greatest fear.
The real reason
you left.
Which was?
That life
with me
would have somehow made you
ordinary.
( chuckling )
You're wonderful.
And am I that transparent?
Only to me.
I wish I could talk to you,
Professor Manheim.
I bet you were really something.
( moaning )
Deanna.
I wanted to see
how he was doing.
The same.
Nothing I do seems
to make any difference.
That's not why you're here.
I thought I was
the empath.
Are you all right?
Why wouldn't I be?
I've got one of the medical
wonders of the galaxy
dying in my Sick Bay.
That's not what
I meant.
I don't think
I want to talk
about what I think
you mean.
Captain Picard...
I can't compete with a ghost
from his past.
No one could.
She's not a ghost.
She's here right now.
She may be in the here and now
but it's the ghost he sees.
Excuse me.
I have to get back
to my patient.
How soon, Mr. Data?
If Dr. Manheim's
information is correct
by my calculations
the next time distortion
should occur
between 28
to 47 minutes.
CRUSHER:
Bridge, this is Sick Bay.
Dr. Manheim is awake and asking
to speak to you, Captain.
Alone.
On my way, Doctor.
You asked for me.
I am not sure
that I remembered all of the
codes for the security system.
You should warn
anyone going down there.
Thank you.
I'll tell them to be cautious.
What I really wanted to talk
to you about is Jenice.
Dr. Manheim, I did not come here
to discuss your wife.
It is only this.
If anything
should go wrong
please take care of her for me.
Of course.
She never would admit this
but she has had a terrible time
these last years.
Had we not been
so isolated
she might have
left me
and I never would have known.
At least, not right away.
Perhaps I am
not a man
who should have
a woman like her.
She deserves better.
You underestimate her.
I know, because
I once did.
In both cases,
the time distortions occurred
along the same continuum
as a preview or a reprise
of a specific point in time.
Where we are,
where we were
and where we will be.
Data, I want this to be
an away team of one-- you.
I don't think there's any reason
to risk anyone else.
It is reasonable, sir.
After all, I
am a machine,
and dispensable.
"Indispensable" is
the appropriate word.
I think it should be
only you
because you seem
more able to control
the effects
of the time distortion.
Oh, I see, sir.
That is quite true, sir.
I see time
as a constant
whereas humans perceive
time as flexible.
Hence the expression
"time flies when
you're having fun"
which, until now, has
always confused me.
Well, I want you
to put a stitch in time
and save
much more than nine.
Sir?
If other members
of the away team
became disoriented
it could create
additional problems
and perhaps increase the danger.
I will go immediately, sir.
Good luck, Data.
All right.
We have the coordinates exactly
as the professor specified.
Enterprise.
Picard.
I am proceeding to the lab, sir.
Maintain an open frequency,
Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
( power humming )
( electrical static )
Mr. Data, what's going on?
Dr. Manheim forgot to mention
one of his security
precautions, sir.
I am proceeding
into the laboratory.
( chiming roar )
PICARD:
Mr. Data, this channel
will remain open.
Please continue to report.
This appears to be
the instrument
Dr. Manheim described.
It should confirm when the
next time effect will occur.
Data, did Manheim give
you enough information
to decipher
the security code?
I will know in a moment, sir.
According to calculations
the next time effect will occur
in one minute, 30 seconds.
What's the next
step, Mr. Data?
I will need to add a specific
amount of antimatter
to rebalance
and align the system.
PICARD:
Will that plug the hole?
Theoretically, yes.
In reality, I do not know.
When the effect hits
the force fields will align
opening a clean, straight path
to the other dimension.
Whatever the time distortion
I must add the antimatter
at the appropriate moment.
Geordi, if the professor
was right
I will need
a 27-second countdown.
You've got it, Data.
Captain, I now have
the antimatter
and am moving towards
the opening
at the end of the lab.
The next time distortion
should occur within seconds.
Geordi, begin countdown
on my mark.
Now.
LA FORGE:
27, 26, 25...
( echoing ):
24-4, 23-3, 22-2, 21-1, 20...
Captain
there appear
to be three of us.
Should I drop
the antimatter
or wait for one of you?
Only one of us
is in the correct
time continuum.
Which one?
Me.
It's me.
LA FORGE:
Fi-fi-five, fo-fo-four,
thr-thr-three
tw-tw-two, one-one-one.
Now-now-now.
PICARD:
Data, report.
Are you all right?
Yes, sir.
PICARD:
Is it closed?
It is well-patched, sir.
Closed indicates
a permanent condition
which I cannot guarantee.
Patched is good enough.
Well done.
Beam back immediately.
With pleasure, sir.
This is amazing.
All your readings are
completely normal.
Where is my wife?
Is she all right?
She's right here.
Jenice.
Paul.
The effect has
been reversed.
I can feel it.
We're safe.
How is he?
He needs rest.
There might be some
residual effects
but other than that,
he'll be all right.
I feel like I am coming
out of a long tunnel.
It's there.
Not at all like I thought
it would be--
different.
Describe it.
I can't. Not yet.
The only words that fit
are too pale
because the images
are so vibrant.
It's not like anything, anyone
has ever experienced before.
There was....
no, no, there is
this kind of life--
not like us, not like this...
What's the condition
of my lab?
Intact, for the most part.
Don't tell me
we're going back.
Oh, Jenice, we are
so close.
We have learned so much
to walk away.
Besides, we owe it
to the others, our friends.
There have been
so many sacrifices
by so many good people.
We'll be going back.
Mm-hmm, yes, I can see that.
I'm sure the Federation
will want to help
in any way that it can.
Thank you.
This time,
it will be different.
I promise.
( laughing )
It always is,
my love.
You said my life
would never be dull
and it never has been.
Thank you.
Computer, this is
Counselor Troi.
Request access.
Do you wish to terminate
the current program?
No, continue the program.
Enter when ready.
The Captain is waiting
for you inside.
How is this possible?
It's Paris.
Unbelievable.
Madame, this way.
The Captain is
waiting for you.
This is so real.
Bien sur. Pourquoi pas?
Jean-Luc, don't tell me
how you did it.
I don't care.
It's perfect.
It's as if we
were really there.
I wanted to say good-bye
properly this time.
( champagne fizzing )
I shall always
picture you here.
( glasses clink )
I expect you to always come
charging to my rescue.
I'll do my best.
Good-bye, Jean-Luc.
Be well.
And you.
Thank you for Paris.
Well, so much for my
dramatically romantic exit.
Is anything
wrong?
No, sir.
Then set course
for Sarona VIII.
As I remember
we were on our way for some
much-needed shore leave.
Course plotted
and laid in, sir.
Warp five.
Engage.
I've only been there once, but
they've got this great club.
I don't remember
the name of it--
they serve those
blue concoctions.
It's across the square
from the Zanza Men's
Dance Palace.
It's called
the Blue Parrot Cafe.
And you're buying.