First Officer's Log,
Stardate 41775.5.
We are en route to the ocean
world of Pacifica.
While our mission
is scientific in nature
we look forward
to the warm, blue waters
and fine beaches that make
Pacifica a jewel of the galaxy.
...so the guy staggers
to his feet
and goes back
to the girl, right?
Well, she smiles, looks him
straight in the eye and says
"just try that in hyperspace."
( laughing )
I see.
So the difficulty in attaining
such complex positioning
in zero gravity environment
coupled with the
adverse effects
it would have on the
psychological well-being
of the average human male
is what makes this anecdote
so amusing.
Yes, very humorous indeed.
Hysterical,
in fact.
( forced laughter )
( chuckling )
What is our E.T.A.
at Pacifica, Mr. La Forge?
22 hours,
14 minutes, sir.
Increase to warp six.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir, full impulse.
Do you think
anyone would object
to our arriving
ahead of schedule?
I know I won't.
I've been really looking
forward to a nice swim.
DATA:
You are aware, Counselor,
that the holodeck
can be programmed
to recreate
an oceanic environment.
Data, it's just
not the same.
Have you ever been for
a real moonlight swim?
One can swim in moonlight?
How about you,
Mr. Worf?
Swimming is too much like...
bathing.
( console beeping )
Commander Riker...
I'm receiving a Code 47.
Verify.
It is Code 47, sir.
Starfleet emergency frequency.
Code 47?
Captain's eyes only.
RIKER: Captain, I'm
sorry to disturb you.
Yes, Number One, what is it?
An incoming message.
Code 47, sir.
Pipe it through.
COMPUTER:
This is an emergency communiqué.
It is not to be discussed
with fellow officers
unless deemed
absolutely necessary.
There will be
no computer record
of said transmission.
Understood.
COMPUTER: Proceed with
voice print identification.
Picard, Jean-Luc.
Captain, USS Enterprise.
( screen hums )
Voice print verified.
Walker.
Hello, Jean-Luc.
It's been a long time.
Too long, old friend.
Why are you contacting me
on this frequency?
It was a difficult decision.
I felt it was worth the risk.
Risk?
It's about Starfleet.
About something we've always
considered to be impossible.
I don't understand.
I can't explain it now.
We need to talk face-to-face.
You're using a Code 47.
I have to know
what all this is about.
Not over subspace. No.
Oh, for God's sake, Walker,
this is a secured channel.
No!
I want you to meet me
on Dytallix B.
When?
Immediately.
No, not possible.
We're expected at Pacifica.
That can wait.
You owe me.
And you owe it to yourself
to hear what I have to say.
Something is beginning.
Don't trust anyone.
Remember that, Jean-Luc.
Don't take anything for granted.
Walker...
Dytallix B.
We'll be waiting.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Data, are you familiar
with Dytallix B?
Dytallix B is one of seven
uninhabited planets
mined for the Federation
by the Dytallix Mining Company.
It is in the nearby
Mira System.
Mr. La Forge, chart a course
for it immediately, warp 7.
And there will be
no records
or logs mentioning
any aspect
of this diversion.
RIKER: Captain, they're
expecting us at Pacifica.
Shouldn't we contact them
and let them know?
Negative.
Nothing goes out
without specific orders
from me.
Hopefully, the delay...
will be minimal.
( beeping, buzzing )
I have the readout
on Dytallix B, Commander.
What have you got?
Dytallix B is
the fifth of six planets
circling the red giant
known as Mira.
One side always
faces the sun
where temperatures reach
up to 180 degrees.
The mines line
the temperate zone
between the day
and night sides
but they are
long deserted.
Why the devil are we
going to this planet?
Are there any miners
or indigenous life-forms
on the planet?
I believe the answer
to both questions is no, sir.
In a manner of speaking
it is nothing
but a lifeless hunk of rock,
a useless ball of mud,
a worthless chunk...
Thank you, Data.
I get the idea.
Captain, we are approaching
Dytallix B.
PICARD: Very good,
Number One. I'm on my way.
WORF:
Captain...
sensors are detecting
three Federation starships
already in orbit
around the planet.
Identify.
Two are
frigates.
The Renegade,
commanded by Tryla Scott
and the Thomas Paine,
Captain Rixx commanding.
DATA: The third is just
coming into range now, sir.
It is Ambassador-class,
heavy cruiser
USS Horatio.
Horatio?
Isn't that
Walker Keel's ship?
Attempts at communication
have been ignored
by all three vessels.
Make no further attempts,
Mr. Worf.
Any life-form readings
on the surface, Data?
Three, sir.
All gathered inside
what appears to be
the entrance
to a mining tunnel.
Very well.
Relay those coordinates
to the Transporter Room.
I'm beaming down.
RIKER:
Alone, Captain?
Alone, Number One.
( wind howling )
Thanks for coming.
This is some greeting,
old friend.
Tell me, Jean-Luc.
Where did we
first meet?
Answer the question.
Tau Ceti III.
It was a bar...
quite an exotic one,
as I remember.
What do I win?
Do you recall the night
you introduced Jack Crusher
to Beverly?
You know full well
that I hadn't met Beverly then.
You introduced them.
My brother introduced them.
You don't have a brother--
two sisters, Anne and Melissa.
What the hell
is all this about?
( sighs )
Apologies, Captain.
We had to be sure
you were really you.
Walker, what is going on?
Captain Picard,
meet Captain Rixx.
I believe we've met--
the Altarian Conference.
And Captain Scott.
Tryla Scott.
It's said you made captain
faster than anyone
in Starfleet history.
Present company included.
Are you that good?
Yes, I am.
Starfleet's finest.
Fancy meeting you here.
We all came secretly, Picard,
to discuss the threat.
What threat?
Have you noticed anything
about Starfleet Command lately?
Anything unusual?
No, but we've been
on the outer rim for a while.
We haven't had much contact
with them.
Some of us have seen
strange patterns emerging.
Unusual orders.
High ranking officials
backing irrational proposals.
Starbase 12 was completely
evacuated for two full days.
No explanation given.
SCOTT:
And what about the deaths?
McKinney...
Ryan Sipe,
Onna Karapleedeez.
All dead?
SCOTT:
A series of accidents.
WALKER:
Or so they say.
It's hard to be
certain of anything.
Interfleet communications
are at a minimum.
But something
is happening.
And we fully expect
the Enterprise
to be targeted soon.
Targeted for what?
By whom?
WALKER:
We're not sure yet.
Damn it, Jean-Luc, I tell you
that some of Starfleet's
top command people are changing.
This could affect the very
core of our organization.
Officers I've known for years
are bluffing their way
through talk
of old times.
That's their weakness--
a lack of memory.
He doesn't
believe us.
He thinks
we're crazy.
You've given me nothing
to believe in.
Just a lot of vague talk
about strange patterns.
Irrational proposals.
Who's behind this,
and to what purpose?
How are people being changed?
I can't say exactly,
but I think it's spread
to my own ship.
My first officer
hasn't been the same
since we stopped off at Earth.
Our medical officer says
he's perfectly normal
but I don't think
I trust him either.
Walker...
We know we don't have
all the answers.
All we ask is that
you keep your eyes open.
That's sound advice
at any time, Captain.
Stay in touch with us.
Covertly.
This meeting
never took place
as far as Starfleet
is concerned.
Please, I'm asking this
as a personal favor.
I'm glad, Jean-Luc.
I'm glad
you're still one of us.
Tell Beverly I...
I said hello.
RIXX:
And watch your back, Picard.
Friends-- close friends--
are few and far between.
Two of the oldest
and closest
are Jack Crusher--
may he rest in peace--
and Walker Keel.
Before various missions
spilt us up,
we were virtually
inseparable.
I trust Keel completely.
If he felt it necessary
to violate regulations,
he must have had
a very good reason.
But you're putting your career
at risk for him.
Friendship must dare to risk,
Counselor,
or it's not friendship.
They illicitly used
the emergency channel
to draw you here.
Then they ask you
to keep secrets
from your
superiors--
effectively, to disobey
Starfleet regulations.
The people involved in this
are of the highest caliber.
If I didn't believe
in their loyalty,
I wouldn't have
gone this far.
Don't you think you should
tell the rest of the crew?
No. I don't want to
risk implicating them...
not until I have
solid evidence
that something
really is wrong.
Take us out of orbit,
Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Resume heading to Pacifica,
warp factor eight.
Aye, sir, warp eight.
At that speed, we should arrive
9.63 hours behind
the original schedule, sir.
Very good. Data, I have
an assignment for you--
one specifically suited
to your talents.
( keyboard beeping )
Computer, this is
Lieutenant Commander Data.
Please access
all Starfleet command orders
to starships, starbases,
and colonies
for the last six months.
COMPUTER:
Working.
PICARD:
Doctor?
I understand
the Horatio
was seen in orbit
around Dytallix.
Did you see Walker?
No.
Oh, I would have loved
to have seen him.
It wasn't possible, Doctor.
Captain, I am picking up
an unusual disturbance
in the nearby quadrant.
Confirmed, sir.
Sector 63.
Specify.
What kind of disturbance?
Hard to say
at this distance, sir.
I guess the trip
to Pacifica will have to wait.
Uh-huh.
Let's investigate.
Maintain speed.
Alter course accordingly.
Aye, sir, changing course to
three-five-one, mark four.
Approaching Sector 63, sir.
Slow to impulse.
Aye, sir,
going to impulse power... now.
Sensors beginning
to pick up small objects, sir.
On screen.
Doesn't look natural.
Agreed.
Enlarge and identify.
WORF:
It looks like...
debris from a space vessel
of some kind.
It could be one of those ships
that was orbiting Dytallix.
We are in close proximity
to that planet.
Identifying marks, Mr. Worf?
Nothing so far.
Sensors not detecting
any bodies in the flotsam.
But from the amount
of the wreckage...
I'm sorry, sir.
It can only be the Horatio.
From the looks of it,
she's been totally destroyed.
Captain's Personal Log,
Stardate 41776.1.
The apparent death
of Walker Keel
has had a powerful impact
on me.
I now believe
there may be a cancer growing
within the ranks of Starfleet.
As a result, I have alerted
my executive officer
to the suspicions voiced
by Keel and the others.
There's no proof
of anything.
The last time
I saw Admiral Quinn,
he tried to warn me
about a subversion
within the Federation.
And Walker tried.
And he's dead.
Subversion?
Personally,
I don't believe
this conspiracy
theory.
DATA:
Startling.
Quite extraordinary, in fact.
COMPUTER:
Direction unclear.
Please repeat request.
That was not a request.
I was simply...
talking to myself.
A human idiosyncrasy
triggered by a fascination
with a particular set of facts.
Or sometimes brought about
by senility.
Or, used as a means
of weighing information
before reaching a conclusion.
Or, as a...
COMPUTER:
Thank you, sir. I comprehend.
( computer beeping )
Please specify how
you would like to proceed, sir.
Please continue
with record scan.
Intriguing.
But if we have no facts,
we have to assume
that the explosion
was an accident.
( door hisses )
Number One, I believe
that what happened
on the Horatio was sabotage.
But if we can't
be certain...
DATA:
Perhaps we can.
My orders were to search
for abnormal patterns
in Starfleet's directives.
I believe I have found
just that.
These are various
outposts and starbases
where I have detected
unusual activity
over the past few months.
What sort of activity?
An uncustomary reshuffling
of personnel--
usually in the command areas.
The new officers
have had frequent contact
with the highest levels
of Starfleet Command.
Why hasn't anyone
discovered this before?
The orders were given
with great subtlety.
To use an aphorism:
Starfleet's left hand
did not know
what its right hand was doing.
Data, can you speculate
as to the purpose
of these reassignments?
I believe it is
a clandestine attempt
to control vital sectors
of Federation territory.
( sighs )
This could be a prelude
to an invasion.
But who's behind it?
There's insufficient data
to make such an assessment, sir.
Are you suggesting
that we warp over to
Starfleet Headquarters
and demand to know
what's going on?
Why not?
PICARD:
Yes, why not?
We're talking about a threat
to the entire future
of the Federation.
I don't think any of us
can rest easy
until we've been to the source.
Captain's Personal Log,
supplemental.
While it is quite unusual
for a starship
to return to Earth,
we seem to be left
with no other choice.
I have apprised
the remaining bridge crew
of our situation.
Approaching
Earth, Captain.
Standard orbit,
Mr. La Forge.
Standard
orbit, sir.
Any word from Starfleet
Command, Data?
Nothing
so far, sir.
Strange.
( console beeps )
Captain, I am now
receiving a message
from Starfleet
Command.
On screen.
Greetings, Enterprise.
I am Admiral Savar.
This is Admiral Aaron.
And I believe you already know
Admiral Quinn.
Yes, indeed. It's good
to see you again, Admiral.
And you, Captain.
Of course,
we are always delighted
when the Enterprise returns
to the nest.
Yet we are puzzled
by the timing of your visit.
Yes, sir, I can imagine
that you would be.
AARON:
Governor Delaplane of Pacifica
informs us
that you canceled
your scheduled stop there.
Is this true?
Yes, sir, it is.
Explain yourself,
Captain.
Why have you
returned to Earth?
I would rather discuss that
in person, Admiral.
Excuse us for one moment,
Captain.
They seem
normal enough.
On the surface.
Counselor,
any thoughts?
Hard to say.
Someone is
hiding something,
but I can't tell
who or what.
I must say I'm not overjoyed
to see Remmick again.
Considering
what we've done,
their response has been
pretty temperate.
I don't like it.
You can't trust them.
SAVAR: Forgive the delay,
Captain Picard.
We'd be delighted
if you and your first officer
would join us for dinner.
Yes, delighted.
It would give you
a good opportunity
to expatiate
your own viewpoint.
To elaborate upon
whatever it is
that's troubling you.
Thank you, we accept
your gracious offer.
SAVAR:
Excellent.
Preparations are
already underway.
We'll greet you in the
reception area in say...
20 minutes?
Splendid.
QUINN: I won't
be able to attend
the dinner, I'm afraid,
but I would like
to see the ship
and say hello
again, Captain.
Of course.
We look forward
to seeing you, Admiral.
Enterprise out.
Quinn wants
to see us alone.
At least we know
he's still on our side.
Mr. Data,
you have the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
( seagulls calling )
Are you ready to beam up
to the Enterprise, sir?
Yes, Commander.
Quite ready.
Energize,
Mr. Remmick.
Welcome aboard,
Greg.
Good to see you.
You remember
Commander Riker.
Hello again,
Commander.
I must say,
you're looking remarkably well.
Never felt better
in my life.
When you were here last,
you were saying that you
were feeling tired.
Tired of life I was,
but not anymore.
I'm ready
for new challenges now.
What about another look
at this ship?
Remember what you told me
back at Relva VII?
About the threat
that you perceived
to the very fabric
of the Federation?
Is that why you're here,
because of what I said?
It's one of
the reasons, yes.
But Jean-Luc...
you took me
far too literally.
I was only referring
to the problems involved
in assimilating new races
into the Federation.
It's an ongoing,
tumultuous process
which can cause
stress and strain
on every aspect
of our alliance.
I'm sorry.
I must have misunderstood.
It's not for you to apologize.
If I led you up
the garden path
I humbly ask
your forgiveness.
Of course.
Now, gentlemen,
you have a dinner
to attend to
and I would like
to go and freshen up
before I look around
a little bit more.
We've arranged
your usual accommodations, sir.
Well, that's outstanding.
Yes, I should be getting
down to the planet.
Commander Riker will
be available here
to show you anything
that you want to see.
It's really
not necessary.
Oh, I insist.
When you've finished
showing the admiral
anything that he needs,
you can join me
down on Earth.
I may want to stay
a while, Jean-Luc.
Of course.
Stay as long
as you wish.
No.
That's not
Gregory Quinn.
It may look like him
and sound like him
but it isn't him.
Are you absolutely
certain, Captain?
I'm certain,
Number One.
Now, I want you
to stay close.
Keep your eye on
his every move.
Have... have Beverly
concoct some reason
for giving him a full
medical examination.
How?
I don't know.
Just do it.
He's a senior admiral.
It's not him, Will.
I know that now.
What I have to find out
is how this has happened
and who or what
is behind it.
Captain,
if you're right...
I'm right.
Should you be beaming
down there alone, unarmed?
I'll take care.
Find out what you
can, then join me.
In force, if necessary.
Energize.
Good luck, sir.
Welcome home,
Captain Picard.
Thank you.
My first officer
will be joining us shortly.
Yes, I'm sure he will.
You've met Commander
Remmick, haven't you?
Under less than
ideal circumstances.
It's nice to see
you again, Captain.
We have prepared a
special meal in your honor.
Delightful.
Tell me, why is
the corridor so quiet?
The last time I was here,
it was bustling with activity.
It usually is.
Tonight's
a quiet night.
Yes.
A quiet night.
( door chimes )
Ready for your
tour, Admiral?
Quite ready,
Commander.
What's in the case?
Actually, I brought it
for Dr. Crusher.
But perhaps you would
like to see it first.
What is it?
A form of life.
It was discovered accidentally
by a survey team
on an uncharted planet.
Why haven't we heard
anything about that?
Oh, you'll be hearing
about it shortly,
but first, there remains much
scientific study to be done.
After all, it is
a superior form of life.
Superior?
Totally.
Come, have a look.
I think I'll summon
my science officer.
It won't like
your science officer.
It does like you!
Vitamins-- they do
wonders for the body.
( groans )
Riker to Security,
Guest Quarter 17.
Emergency.
( menacing chuckle )
Let's have some Andonian tea
while we wait for your Riker.
Then you can tell us
about what's brought you here.
I see you keep up
with our duty roster.
Yes, of course, Captain.
The Enterprise
is very important to us.
Excuse me,
gentlemen.
To the Horatio,
The Horatio.
What an awful tragedy.
Such a terrible loss of life.
It's interesting that
you should mention the Horatio.
It's one of the subjects
I wanted to discuss.
AARON:
Really?
Has the cause of her destruction
been ascertained?
Absolutely.
Implosion.
Due to the extreme
negligence of her captain.
Enjoy, Picard.
I believe you'll find it
an excellent aperitif.
QUINN:
It's a good thing you're here.
He slipped and
hit his head.
This is Lieutenant La Forge
in Guest Quarter 17.
We have a medical emergency.
Your Dr. Crusher
is most capable.
I'm sure he'll
be all right.
Now, if you'll
excuse me,
my time here
is most limited.
Admiral...
Don't you think
we should wait
till the doctor gets here?
Now, Klingon,
it's between you and me.
( growls )
Do Klingons fear death
as much as humans?
I could snap your
neck in a second,
but it wouldn't be as much fun.
( groaning )
Ooh!
Are you all right?
Oh, if I could see,
I'd be seeing stars.
What is he?
Let's find out.
Retinal scans
are an exact match.
It really is Quinn.
How can that be?
The man picked me up
like a rag doll.
I'm going to have to do
a complete internal scan.
Keep me posted, Doctor.
I'll be on the Bridge.
What is that?!
What do you know
of conspiracies, Captain?
Not nearly enough,
I suppose.
That's the charming thing
about them, isn't it?
When a machination is real,
no one knows about it.
And when it's suspected,
it's almost never real.
Except, of course,
in paranoid delusions
for those
who believe.
Sorry to interrupt.
Dinner is served.
Wonderful.
Bantering with the captain
has given me quite an appetite.
I need to contact
my ship
to let Commander Riker know
that we're about to sit down.
Of course,
Captain.
We'll wait for you
at the table.
Picard to Riker.
Dr. Crusher here, Captain.
May I speak freely?
I suppose I have little choice.
Where is Riker?
He was attacked by Quinn.
Or what we thought was Quinn.
Specify, Doctor.
A parasitic being
has invaded Quinn's body.
It has complete control
over all brain functions.
It seems to breathe
through a small gill
protruding from the back
of Quinn's neck.
Look for this, Captain.
I believe it will be visible
on anyone
who has been compromised.
Any idea of what it is
or where it came from?
Negative, I've never seen
anything like it before.
( beep )
DATA: Lieutenant Worf,
if the situation
is under control,
please report to the Bridge.
Doctor?
It's okay.
He won't be waking up
for a long time.
Continue, Doctor.
By the placement
of the tendrils,
the parasite appears
to stimulate
the victim's adrenal glands,
generating great strength
and resistance to the...
Never mind the details.
Can you remove it?
I don't think so.
Not without killing the patient.
Captain, you must set
your phaser on kill.
Stun has little effect.
Doctor, one does not beam down
to Starfleet Headquarters armed.
Your food
is getting cold, Captain.
I'm going
into dinner now, Doctor.
Tell Commander Riker to join me
as soon as he's ready.
Picard out.
( gasps )
Please, sit down,
Captain.
We've been waiting.
Go ahead and start, Captain.
We don't stand on ceremony here.
( groans )
Oh, do eat up, Picard.
Raise your hand
if you want seconds.
Riker, thank God.
We're leaving.
You're not going anywhere.
You'll be one of us soon.
You were meant
for the doctor.
It couldn't be helped.
Riker walked in on us
unexpectedly.
No matter.
The doctor will be
joining us soon.
All in good time.
SAVAR:
Well, Captain Scott, good.
Now, the setting is complete.
You don't really think
we were in the dark
about your intentions,
do you?
SAVAR: Patience is one of
our virtues, Captain.
We didn't
go after you.
We allowed you to come after us.
More dramatic that way,
don't you think?
Yes, the one thing
both races share
is a love
of theater.
And you've put
on a fine show.
What race are you?
Where are
you from?
SAVAR:
It's not important.
Let us just say
we've come a long way
to join you.
It's a perfect match.
We're the brains.
You're the brawn.
You'll understand soon, Picard.
SAVAR:
Indeed.
We've been moving slowly,
cautiously for many months now.
Careful to cover
our tracks,
careful not to
arouse suspicion
until it's too late.
And now, it's too late.
For you, that is.
Well said, brother.
Picard and Riker
control the Enterprise,
which means we control
the Enterprise.
Eat hearty, brother.
Relish your new body.
( groaning )
Aaron!
( yelling )
( high-pitched beeping )
Can I help you, gentlemen?
Is there any
trouble here?
Perhaps if you'd tell me
what it is...
Remmick...
No, Will.
You don't understand.
( gurgling )
We mean you no harm.
We seek peaceful co-existence.
( shrill screeching )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 41780.2.
How difficult after all
these years of learning
to respect life,
to be forced to destroy it.
But there seems to be
no alternative.
Admiral Quinn is expected
to make a full recovery.
There is no trace
of the parasite
which took control of him.
We'll never know
how many of these life-forms
infiltrated Starfleet
but it seems
they could not survive
without the mother creature
which had taken over
Commander Remmick.
It was Dr. Crusher's idea
to simulate the blue gill.
We had to make sure it would
fool everyone, including you.
That it did, Number One.
Rest assured.
DATA:
Captain?
I have attempted to trace
the message Remmick was sending.
I believe
it was aimed
at an unexplored
sector of our galaxy.
Any idea
what the message was, Data?
I believe
it was a beacon.
A beacon?
Yes, sir.
A homing beacon.
Sent from Earth.
( high-pitched beeping )