First Officer's Log,
Stardate 41986.0.
We are awaiting the return
of Captain Picard
who was summoned
to Starbase 7-1-8
for an emergency conference.
Meanwhile, our sensors
have been monitoring
an ancient capsule floating in
our vicinity,
which appears to
be from Earth.
I wonder how it got out here.
At its present speed and heading
it will eventually enter
the Kazis
binary system
and will certainly
be destroyed.
I could attach a tractor beam
and adjust its heading.
I think not, Mr. Worf.
It's just a piece
of space debris.
If we hadn't been sitting here,
waiting for the Captain
we wouldn't have noticed it.
Let it be.
Let nature
take its course.
How long until
Captain Picard returns?
The last
communication
indicated it would
be several hours.
Commander--
request permission to
investigate this vehicle.
Why, Data?
It's just a derelict.
It is a piece
of history.
The opportunity to examine
such an ancient vehicle
does not come around
very often.
And, as you
pointed out
we do have the time.
Very well.
Be prepared to beam back
before the Captain returns.
Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant Worf,
go with him.
Aye, sir.
Minimal oxygen
atmosphere.
An ancient
solar generator--
still operating.
WORF:
Commander,
look at this.
The on-board computers
have ceased functioning.
I may be able to download
this old-style disk drive
back to
the Enterprise.
( beeping )
( distant clanging )
( grunting )
Must be
sealed.
Probably
with age.
Ah, not necessary.
The seal has been broken
and the environment corrupted.
Here's another.
This one is empty.
Commander
look
at this.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Were they frozen for
an extended journey?
If that were the purpose,
there would be evidence
of a more sophisticated
monitoring system.
These containers were designed
solely for refrigeration.
The Captain's shuttle
is approaching
the main Shuttle Bay, sir.
Enterprise,
this is the Captain.
Number One,
I want to get underway
as soon as the shuttle
is secure.
Aye, sir.
We'll make all preparations.
Commander Data--
return to the Enterprise,
immediately.
DATA:
We have run into
an unusual situation, sir.
There are people on board--
frozen.
Frozen? How many?
Three.
The vehicle has suffered
severe damage.
Most of her systems
have failed.
Are you suggesting they be
transferred to the Enterprise?
I do not believe we should
leave them here, sir.
With your permission
we will be returning
with three containers.
RIKER:
Whatever you do, do it quickly.
Mr. La Forge, set course
zero-five-eight
mark one-seven-three.
Laying
it in, sir.
Number One,
I want a staff meeting
on the Observation Deck.
Captain
those coordinates will take us
right into the
Neutral Zone.
That is correct, Mr. La Forge.
Warp factor eight.
Aye, sir. Warp eight.
Engage.
Two Federation outposts
in sector three-zero
have been destroyed.
There's been no communication
with Federation starbases
in sector three-one
since Stardate 41903.2.
Romulans.
That's the assumption.
There's been
no direct contact
with the Romulans
since the Tomed incident.
The questions are: why now?
What's their
objective?
For 50 years, there's barely
a whisper out of them
and now, for no apparent reason
they seem to be back
with a roar.
Everything we know about them
is based on rumor
or conjecture.
The strategic decision
is to send one ship.
The Enterprise.
We could get out there
and find ourselves
greatly overmatched.
True enough.
It's a gamble.
This first encounter--
coming so suddenly
after all this time--
we have to assume it's a setup.
If force is necessary,
we will use it
but that will mean
we have failed.
Our goal here is to establish
some kind of relations
with the Romulans.
If we don't
succeed
then, to convince them
of our resolve.
The general feeling at Starfleet
is that they are seeking
confrontation.
They may want
to test themselves
in battle
against a Federation starship.
See how far we have advanced.
If that is the case,
then I need to know it.
Counselor, I
shall need a full
profile on them.
There is limited information
but I will
prepare something.
Computer, estimated time
of arrival at the Neutral Zone?
19 hours, 28 minutes.
Let's reassemble
in six hours.
Stay sharp, no surprises.
I would rather outthink them
than outfight them.
Questions?
What is it,
Doctor?
It's the people
from the capsule.
Capsule? People?
What people?
The people
Data beamed over.
I wasn't aware
that he had.
Well, he did
and they were frozen.
I thawed them.
You what?
Well, I didn't know
what else to do.
The crypts
in which they were frozen
were literally falling apart.
So, what's their condition?
Right now, they're all sleeping.
Each of them needed
minor medical attention.
Minor now but, then,
their conditions
were obviously terminal.
One had a heart problem
another, an advance
case of emphysema
with extensive
liver damage.
You know, the most surprising
thing of all
is that each of them had been
frozen after they died.
After they died?
Cryonics.
It was a kind of fad
in the late 20th century.
People feared
dying.
It terrified them.
So, at the moment of death
they would be frozen
so that later,
sometime in the future
presumably, when
medical science
had found a cure
for whatever
killed them--
they could be
thawed back to life, healed
and sent on
about their business.
Well, in the case of this group,
it apparently worked.
Mr. Data, will you report
to Sick Bay...
...immediately.
Look, I am
never critical
of any member of
my staff being
curious, but...
it's just that
the timing is so...
I could not
leave them there, Captain.
The condition of their vehicle
was deteriorating.
But, Data,
they were already dead.
I mean, what more could have
happened to them?
I see your point,
Captain
but, at the time, it seemed
the proper thing to do.
Well, they're
alive now.
We're going to have to treat
them as living human beings.
Alive and well and ready
to be awakened.
Look, before you
wake them up
I want to have
security here.
Lieutenant Worf,
report to Sick Bay.
I have them
sedated now
but they should be
up and about
as soon as
possible.
Well, then we have
no other choice.
None that
I can see.
Welcome to the 24th century.
I was able to retrieve
some information
from the ancient disk I removed
from the module's computer.
Her name
is Clare Raymond--
age 35
occupation,
homemaker.
Must be some kind
of construction work.
She died of an embolism.
It probably happened
very suddenly.
Otherwise, her physical
condition was excellent.
His name is
Ralph Offenhouse--
age, 55;
occupation, financier.
Advanced
cardiomyopathy.
Inoperable
at the time
but easily
correctable now.
He must have known
his condition was terminal
for quite
some time.
Much of his file, we
could not retrieve.
His name is
L.Q. Sonny Clemonds.
Apparently, his occupation
had something to do with music.
CRUSHER:
There was marked deterioration
in every system of his body.
Probably from massive
chemical abuse.
Unbelievable.
Sounds like someone
who hated life
yet he had himself
frozen, presumably
so he could go
through it all again.
Too afraid to live,
too scared to die.
Well, Doctor, this
seems to be a situation
more suited
to your talents.
I'll leave it
with you.
I'll be on the Bridge.
Number One, kindly
take charge of our guests
until we have time to decide
what we are going
to do with them.
Aye, sir.
And, Number One--
keep them out
of my way.
I know this is all
very confusing to you
so I'll attempt
to explain.
You are on
the starship USS Enterprise
American?
No, it's a vessel
of the United Federation
of Planets
and Earth is
a member.
Uh, what year is this?
By your
calendar--
2364.
What?
My heart, is it...
It's perfectly fine.
In fact, all of you
are now in excellent health.
It worked.
I made it.
What is that?
An android.
You mean a robot?
Actually, there is
a distinct difference
between an android and a robot.
And him-- the one
I saw before with the head?
She means Worf.
He's a Klingon.
That takes a little more
explanation.
Now, listen, guys.
I paid some idiot
a lot of money
to freeze me
when I died
and I just got to hear
the words.
Am I alive?
Oh, yes, absolutely.
And the liver that was
about to explode in my face?
Perfectly sound.
Excuse me.
Could someone please tell me
what's going on here?
About 370 years ago,
you died of a massive embolism.
I don't remember anything
about that.
You and the others were frozen.
Cryonics-- you know, it's freeze
you now and heal you later.
Yeah, I've heard of it.
I just never gave it
much thought.
How did we get here?
You were in a space module.
The whacko that sold
me this scam said
that by putting us in orbit
there wasn't going to be
no chance of a brownout.
Yes, several cryonics companies
fell into disrepute
because of power failures
which adversely affected
their refrigeration system.
Their stocks were
severely depressed.
The whole deal was a long shot
but, I figured, what the hell
might as well
give them the dough
instead of leaving it
to my ex-wives.
( Sonny laughs )
But, you know, son,
I just figured
it was all a bunch of hooey.
"Hooey?"
Ah, as in hogwash,
malarkey, jive--
an intentional fabrication.
There you go.
Now you got it.
Now, if you didn't contract
for this, who did?
It must have been
my husband, Donald.
If it was new and foolish,
he would have popped for it.
Well, I'll say this for it--
it's the first thing he's
ever bought into that worked.
I, for one, never had a doubt.
My stock in this company
must have split at least
a dozen times by now.
Actually,
the process
of cryonics
was never more than a fad
and did not continue much
beyond the mid-21st century.
Uh-huh.
I need to make a phone call
as soon as possible.
A phone call?
Yes, I have provided
for myself.
I have
a substantial portfolio.
It's critical
that I check on it.
Let the bank know
that I'm alive and well.
Uh, that's going to be a little
difficult right at the moment.
Well, do you at least have a
copy of the Wall Street Journal?
I think we should take
the Doctor's advice.
Take this very slowly
until we've all adjusted.
And then we'll talk
to the Captain.
As you know, sir, there is
very little available
on the Romulans.
Counselor, anything
will be helpful.
They seem to be
creatures of extremes.
One moment, violent
beyond description
the next, tender.
They are related
to Vulcans
but, as each race
developed
their differences
grew wider.
They're intensely
curious.
Their belief in their own
superiority is beyond arrogance.
For some reason,
they have exhibited
a fascination
with humans
and it is that fascination,
more than anything else
that has kept the peace.
One other thing,
they will not initiate anything.
They will wait for you
to commit yourself.
Counterpunches.
Thank you, Counselor.
That's quite valuable.
Talk.
I'd like me a thick
Kansas City steak
and some country-fried potatoes
and a mess
of greens.
Oh, hell, just forget all that
and give me a martini
straight up with two olives...
for the vitamins.
Whoo.
Is something wrong?
Wrong?
Well, only
that your computer here
fixed about the best martini
I ever had.
I might just get
to like this place.
Let's see
if the Braves are on.
How do you
cut on this TV?
TV?
Yeah, the
boob tube.
I'd like to see how the Braves
are doing after all this time.
Probably still finding
ways to lose.
I believe he
means television, sir.
That particular form
of entertainment
did not last much
beyond the year 2040.
Well, what do you guys do?
I mean, you don't drink
and you ain't got no TV.
Must be kind of boring,
ain't it?
PICARD:
Number One.
Riker here.
Would you and Mr. Data
report to the Bridge?
At once, sir.
Uh, with whom
were you speaking?
The Captain.
Good, would you tell him
that I would like to see him
as soon as it's convenient.
What's going to
happen to us?
Do we stay
here with you?
Do we go back
to Earth?
That will all be
up to the Captain.
Well, get him in here.
I have to phone
Geneva right away
about my accounts.
( chuckles )
Why, the interest alone
could be enough
to buy this ship.
The Yankee's right.
Let's get the big boy in here.
I'll pass along your request.
If you'll excuse us.
Duty calls--
hey, I understand.
Why don't you come back later
on, and you and me will find us
a couple low-mileage
pit woffies
and help them
build a memory.
What is to be done
with them, sir?
I don't know.
Commander--
"a low-mileage pit woffie"?
This time
you've got me.
I haven't a clue.
They are the most
unusual humans
I have ever encountered.
Well, from what I've
seen of our guests
there's not much
to redeem them.
Makes one wonder how
our species survived
the 21st century.
Report.
We are six hours
from the Neutral Zone.
I've been unable
to establish communications
with any Federation colony
or station
in this vicinity.
How many outposts are
there in this sector?
Nine.
I think we should work
under the assumption
that they've
all been destroyed.
By the Romulans?
It fits
their historical pattern.
DATA:
Since we have had
no contact with the Romulans
for 53 years, seven
months, 18 days
we must consider
that the information
we do have is
out of date.
RIKER:
The positive side of
that is that the information
they have about us is
also out of date.
Captain, I think it's
that lack of information
that this is all about.
Go on.
In my opinion, the Romulans
want a confrontation
specifically with us.
The Enterprise?
Well, not by name,
but the Federation.
They know that the Federation
will send their best.
That will give them
a perfect chance
to see firsthand
how far we've advanced
both in technology
and technique.
What are you recommending?
I'm not sure I have
a specific recommendation.
Perhaps, we should
assume the initiative.
WORF:
I agree
with Commander Riker.
This may be
our only opportunity.
We should
seize it.
Mr. Data?
The strategy is built
on a single premise--
the hostile intent
of the Romulans.
If the premise is sound,
so is the proposal.
LA FORGE:
If their intention
isn't hostile
what is it?
OFFENHOUSE:
Captain Picard!
This is
Captain Picard.
To whom
am I speaking?
Ralph Offenhouse.
I need to talk to you.
What is going on here,
Number One?
Did you give him permission
to contact me?
Of course not, he must have
seen me use the com panel.
Ah, listen, Mr., um, Offenhouse
we're in a very important
conference right now.
I'm sick and tired
of being put off
by you and your staff.
This is the worst run ship
I have ever been on.
You should take some lessons
from the Q.E. II.
Now that's
an efficient operation.
Data, identify.
What is a "Q.E. II"?
It was a passenger liner
which mostly traveled
Earth's Atlantic Ocean
during the late 20th
and early 21st centuries.
He's comparing the Enterprise
to a cruise ship?
Captain Picard,
I demand that you see me!
I think I have been
very, very patient.
I demand a phone or a radio
or whatever else you have
but frankly,
enough is enough.
Especially
under the circumstances
and considering what I paid
for this procedure.
I must make contact
with my law...
( door opens )
I'm Captain Picard.
Excellent.
Now maybe we'll be able
to get some things
straightened out.
We may indeed.
Those com panels are for
official ship business.
Well, if they're so important
why don't they
need an executive key?
Aboard a starship vessel,
that is not necessary.
We are all capable
of exercising
self-discipline.
Now, you will refrain
from using them.
Now, just a minute.
We are in
a very serious
and potentially
dangerous situation.
I'm sure whatever
it is seems very
important to you
but my situation
is far more critical.
I don't think you are aware
of your situation
or of how much time has passed.
Believe me, I am fully cognizant
of where I am and when.
It is simply
that I have more to protect
than a man in your position
could possibly imagine.
No offense meant,
but a military career
has never been considered
to be upwardly mobile.
I must contact my lawyer.
Your lawyer has been dead
for centuries.
Yes, of course I know that
but he was a full partner
in a very important firm.
Rest assured, that firm
is still operating.
That's what all this is about.
A lot has changed
in the past 300 years.
People are no longer obsessed
with the accumulation of things.
We've eliminated hunger, want,
the need for possessions.
We've grown out of our infancy.
You've got it all wrong.
It has never been
about possessions--
it's about power.
Power to do what?
To control your life,
your destiny.
That kind of control
is an illusion.
Really?
I'm here, aren't I?
I should be dead
but I'm not.
( sobbing )
What is it?
I don't know, it just started,
and it won't stop.
I keep thinking
about my boys.
Counselor Troi, will you
report to the guest lounge?
RIKER:
Captain, we are approaching
Science Station Delta Zero-Five.
Slow to half-impulse.
I'm on my way.
CLEMONDS:
Captain,
I need to see
that pretty little doctor
of yours.
I'll inform her.
Captain, I didn't mean
to come on so strong.
It's just that I've
built my whole life
on knowing
what's going on
and for the first time,
I feel...
completely out of touch.
It's, uh, making me crazy.
You can understand that?
It's the first thing you've
said I do understand.
I'll see what I can do.
And please stay
off the com panels.
Counselor, will you get
those people under control.
We cannot afford this
continuing distraction.
Yes, sir.
( door chimes )
Hello.
My name's Deanna.
They sent you here
to settle me down?
I'm the Ship's
Counselor.
I thought you
might want to talk.
The local shrink?
I'm sorry,
I'm not familiar
with that term.
It doesn't matter.
You're feeling profoundly sad.
I can't stop crying.
I miss my sons.
And then I think, "I'm here,
but they're gone."
Donald--
that's my husband--
I love that man but,
good intentions aside,
he'd mess up a free lunch.
Why on Earth he ever
decided to do this.
He must have thought
you would have wanted it.
No, I can tell you
exactly what happened.
He couldn't think
about going on alone.
I died, and he
couldn't face it, so...
he figured he'd
have me frozen
and then, in his mind,
I wasn't really gone.
Sounds crazy but
you'd have
to know Donald.
I wish I knew what happened
to my children.
Did they get married?
Did they have kids?
Let's see if we can find out.
Computer, this
is Counselor Troi.
Request personal
history on...
What are their names?
Tommy-- he's eight
and Eddie's five.
COMPUTER:
Full names, date
and place of birth.
Um, they were born
in Secaucus.
That's in Jersey.
Can this
really work?
Can this tell me what's happened
to them?
Well, there must be a record
somewhere.
There's a good chance
we can find it.
Well, whether we do or not,
I want to thank you...
for trying.
Date of birth--
Tommy was born February 17.
Well, I just
got to have
a little something to jump-start
the morning
and a little something else
to shut down the night.
You have no medical need.
Well, it ain't a matter
of "need" darling.
It's a matter
of survival.
Sorry.
Not to worry.
Ol' Wade Toss'll scuffle
along the best way he can.
How do I get hold of that fella
with the strange-looking face?
I beg your pardon.
What's his name--
that, uh, android fella.
You mean
Lieutenant Commander Data?
That's the one.
I'll let him know
you're looking for him.
Much obliged.
You know, you just
about the prettiest
little ol' doctor
I ever seen.
Much obliged.
This is amazing.
It's all right here.
Ten generations
of your progeny.
Everyone I've
ever known is dead.
Do you mind?
I'd like to be alone.
No, not at all.
( door chimes )
You asked to see me?
Hey, look, I'm about
to go out of my mind
for something to do.
I mean, sitting here
alone just don't get it.
Now, what say you
and I put together
a little party.
A celebration?
No, nothing that fancy.
Just some folks, some
suds and some sounds.
Why, hell, it ain't nothing
but something to do.
I will speak
to the Captain.
Great, you do that.
Inquiry.
You do not seem
to be having as much
difficulty adjusting
to your current
circumstances
as the others.
You mean being here
on this tub
400 years from
where I started?
Oh, heck, it's the same dance,
it's just a different tune.
You think anybody here's got
a guitar I could borrow?
No, but the computer can
replicate such an instrument.
I was kind of hoping
to get one
while I still
remembered the chords.
RIKER:
Commander Data, we are
approaching the Neutral Zone.
Report to the Bridge.
I must leave now.
What's this "neutral zone"?
It is a buffer
between the Romulan Empire
and the Federation.
Why does that make me nervous?
I do not know.
Well, we won't
be inviting
these Romulans
to our party, will we?
No, that would
not be... appropriate.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have arrived at the edge
of the Neutral Zone
where we will now have
an opportunity
to learn firsthand
what happened
to our distant outposts.
Captain, there is nothing left
of Outpost
Delta Zero-Five.
Must have been one hell
of an explosion.
Sensors indicate no evidence
of conventional attack.
Can you determine
what happened?
The outpost was not
just destroyed.
It is as though
some great force
just scooped it off
the face of the planet.
Could it have been
a natural phenomenon?
Insufficient
information, sir.
Mr. La Forge.
Sir?
Set course for the next
closest station.
Aye, sir.
I have spent my entire career
being able to tell
when the other guy's mouth
is dry.
There is something
going on here.
Something serious.
The tension level
on this ship has jumped up.
CLEMONDS:
Well, even if
you're right
what can we do about it?
And besides, these ol' boys here
don't need us
tellin' 'em
where the bear sits.
Look here what that
young fella
made for me.
How did he do that?
He called it
a pattern replication.
It plays real good, too.
I am trying to tell you that
there is a situation developing
on this vessel
that directly affects us
and all you can talk about
is that stupid guitar.
Hey, now these folks don't need
us swimming in their soup.
So, why don't you just relax
and let them do their jobs?
Well, that may be
all right for you
but I am not willing
to allow my fate
to be decided
by others.
I, at least, want to know
what is going on.
We are approaching
Tarod Nine.
The condition
is identical, Captain.
Everyone and
everything is gone.
RIKER:
Captain--
I strongly recommend
that we go to red alert.
If the Romulans have improved
their cloaking device--
and we'd be fools
to believe they haven't--
we should assume
a more defensive posture.
I agree, Captain.
I recommend we go
immediately to battle stations.
I appreciate your
advice and concern
but this is not the time
for rash actions.
We are still investigating.
There are three other stations
in this sector we have to visit.
Let's proceed in a calm
and orderly manner.
If not battle stations,
may we at least take the ship
to yellow alert?
Yes, Number One,
that would be prudent.
Make it so.
( beeping )
COMPUTER:
All decks, yellow alert.
Um... let's see, uh...
I want to go to the, uh...
to the, um...
Where would the Captain be?
( beeping )
COMPUTER:
Captain Picard is located
on the Main Bridge.
Well then, take me
to the Main Bridge.
Captain, my sensors
indicate a disturbance.
It is large and moving, but I
cannot get a positive lock.
Nor can I get it
on the viewscreen.
Shields up.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Captain, I recommend we transfer
all power to the phasers
and arm
the photon torpedoes.
Wait, if that is
a Romulan ship, they
will read our intent.
It will force them into taking
up a similar posture.
We don't want
to engage in battle.
Captain, this is
sufficient evidence.
Outposts have been destroyed.
Countless lives
have been lost.
WORF:
I have
a positive lock.
They're disengaging
their cloaking device.
They'll only be vulnerable
for an instant
as they become visible.
Captain, this may be
our only chance.
No.
Where are they?
WORF:
The signal
is weakening.
I've lost them.
Damn.
Mr. Data, your sensors
picking up anything?
You should be
detecting a disturbance.
Negative, sir.
We wanted to know if they had
improved the cloaking device.
Guess we have our answer.
They were trying to determine
our intent.
They wanted to see
if we would fire.
Who the hell are "they?"
Get that man off
the Bridge now.
I'm not going anywhere.
WORF:
Captain!
They're back.
Amazing.
I never thought I'd see
a Romulan vessel.
Not this close.
The last time we
encountered them
was decades ago.
It cost thousands of lives.
I can believe that.
Stay calm, everyone.
Open hailing frequencies.
Captain, these are Romulans.
They are without honor.
They killed my parents
in an attack on Khitomer
when they were supposed
to be our allies.
They believe humans and Klingons
are a waste of skin.
Lieutenant, control
your emotions.
Please open
hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open.
Romulan vessel, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
Sensors indicate all
of their systems are armed, sir.
But they have not fired.
I am Commander Tebok.
Commander, you have crossed
the Neutral Zone.
This is Federation territory.
It was necessary.
It might be viewed
as an act of aggression.
If our intent
were aggression
you would not
be here now.
If we go to war
let us be sure it is
for the right reason.
We are here
because our outposts
which border
on the Neutral Zone
were also attacked.
Destroyed in the exact
same manner as your own.
Even so, what gives them
the right
to enter
Federation space?
Silence your dog,
Captain.
Lieutenant Worf's question
is valid.
To even ask
such a question
implies that we
need permission.
We do not.
Do you think
that we attacked
your outposts?
Once we realized
the level of destruction
we knew it could not
have been you.
Who is responsible?
They haven't got a clue.
They're hoping
you know
but they're
too arrogant to ask.
You're out of line, mister.
Yes, but it's
a correct assessment.
We do not know
who is responsible.
Why entire outposts
on both sides
have been carried off.
I would like
to offer a proposal.
An alliance?
Between the Romulans
and the Federation?
Nothing so grandiose.
Just this... cooperation.
There was an intent here.
Whoever or whatever did this
is more powerful
than either of us.
Let's collaborate.
Let's share whatever
we learn about what
has happened here.
Agreed, on
this one issue
and only if it
is convenient
and appropriate
at the time.
Captain Picard
because
your actions
are those of
a thoughtful man
I'll tell you this.
Matters more urgent
caused our absence.
Now, witness
the result.
Outposts
destroyed
expansion of
the Federation
everywhere.
Yes, we have indeed
been negligent, Captain
but no more.
Commander, we have made
some progress here.
Let's not ruin it
with unnecessary posturing.
Your presence
is not wanted.
Do you understand
my meaning, Captain?
We are back.
I think our lives just became
a lot more complicated.
Get him off my Bridge.
I found something.
I've been able
to locate a family
living just outside
of Indianapolis.
The man's name
is Thomas Raymond.
That's my son's name.
My son's name is Tommy.
Computer, let us see
Thomas Raymond.
RAYMOND:
Oh, my God.
That's Donald.
That's my husband.
Actually, it's
your great, great, great,
great, great grandson.
He's the spitting image.
Well, I have
his address.
When you get back to Earth
you can go
and see him.
No, I'll be out of time.
A relic.
Perhaps.
But it's a place to start.
After all,
he is family.
There's no denying that.
Here's what I propose.
You can't stay
on the Enterprise
but I have arranged
for us to rendezvous
with the USS Charleston
bound for Earth.
They will
deliver you there.
Then what will
happen to us?
There's no trace
of my money.
My office is gone.
What will I do?
How will I live?
This is the 24th century.
Material needs no longer exist.
Then what's the challenge?
The challenge, Mr. Offenhouse,
is to improve yourself
to enrich
yourself.
Enjoy it.
Well, one good thing is
since everybody
has forgotten
everything
I ever did
it will all be
brand spanking new.
I'll be a bigger hit
than I ever was.
Perhaps so.
Anything is possible.
What say, son?
You'd make a hell
of a sideman.
That offer does present
a certain fascination.
Captain, I've
plotted a course
to intercept
the Charleston
but they've
just informed me
that they'll be making
an extended stop
at Arloff Nine.
Your point,
Mr. La Forge?
Well, at warp eight,
we could have our guests
at Starbase 39 Sierra
in five days.
Take months off their journey.
But they'll benefit
from the extended time
it will allow
them to acclimate
before returning to Earth.
RIKER:
It's a pity we can't
take them there ourselves.
Having them on board
is like a visit from the past.
That would take us
in the wrong direction.
Our mission is
to go forward
and it's just begun.
Set velocity warp six,
Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
Warp six.
There is still much to do.
Still so much to learn.
Mr. La Forge, engage.