COMPUTER:
Repulse Shuttle has cleared
Docking Bay Three.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing
frequencies open.
Repulse,
this is the Enterprise.
We are getting underway.
MAN:
Acknowledged, Enterprise.
Transfer complete.
Good luck on your mission.
And to you.
MAN:
Give my regards to your Captain.
Repulse out.
Shuttle Bay
is secure, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Crusher.
Make all preparations
to get underway.
We're constructing the enclosure
on Cargo Deck Five.
( door chimes )
Come.
The transfer's
been completed.
Dr. Pulaski is being shown
to her quarters.
We're ready
to get underway.
Grand.
Take a look
at the containment module
our Chief Engineer has designed.
"Chief Engineer"--
it still has a nice ring to it.
Each of these units will have
total environmental control--
gravity, temperature,
atmosphere, light--
all in a protective
stasis field.
And these get put
into the large containment unit?
Right.
See, these modules will keep
the specimens alive
but it's
this large containment area
that's going to keep us alive.
I have to go and replicate this
512 times
which means I'll have
to divert power
from the warp engines
to the replicator for a while.
Oh.
How long will we be
on impulse power?
Couple of hours.
Can't be helped.
When we leave 'audet IX
I'm going to need
all the power you can slam
into those warp engines.
You'll have it.
Number One, I'll
relieve you at 0300.
Take us out of orbit,
Mr. Crusher.
Set course for 'audet IX.
Aye, sir.
Course for 'audet IX
has been input.
Maximum impulse velocity.
Aye, sir.
Engage.
Engineering,
this is Science One.
I have just observed
what appeared to be
a random energy transference.
Where?
Aft. Outboard
of the port nacelle.
Hold on, I'll check.
No, I show nothing here, Data.
Problem, Commander?
Possibility, sir.
An unexplained
power fluctuation.
You let me know
if it reoccurs.
Aye, sir.
( tinkling whoosh )
( distorted voices )
Huh.
( tinkling whoosh )
( groaning softly )
( muted tinkling buzz )
( heavy breathing )
( gasping )
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42073.1.
There has been an outbreak of
an unclassified
plasma plague
in the Rachelis System.
We're on an emergency run
to collect specimens
of the deadly plague
and transport them to
Science Station Tango Sierra
where hopefully an antidote
can be produced.
How's it going?
Finished.
Just waiting
to insert the modules.
Number One.
Lieutenant La Forge
says we will be able
to engage the warp drive
within the hour.
Grand.
Mr. Data, when we have
a complete list
of all the specimens
we will be carrying,
I want you and Doctor, uh...
Pulaski, sir.
Dr. Pulaski.
I want you
to go through them.
Aye, sir.
By the way, where
is our new doctor?
Has she reported in?
Not yet.
Sick Bay, this
is the Captain.
MAN:
Sick Bay, aye.
Is Dr. Pulaski there?
MAN:
Uh, no, sir.
The Doctor is in Ten-Forward.
Thank you.
MAN:
Aye, sir.
A few hours on board
and already
she's found Ten-Forward?
I'll go get her.
No.
I'll go.
Not the best way
to meet your new Captain.
Deck Ten, Forward
Station One.
Hello, Captain.
Ensign.
I'm, uh, sorry
this mission
will delay your reunion
with your mother.
That's all right.
It will give me
the time to finish
some projects
I have to do.
It's going to be hard
leaving the Enterprise.
Mixed feelings
for all of us.
It's always hard
leaving any ship.
Just as it was
for your mother
when she left to become
Head of Starfleet Medical.
But moving from one
assignment to another
is part of the life
which you're choosing.
I know.
But this isn't any ship.
How true.
( buzz of conversation )
Guinan.
Captain.
Where is Dr. Pulaski?
Thank you.
Dr. Katherine Pulaski?
Ah, you must be
Captain Picard.
Doctor, protocol may have been
lax on your last assignment
but here on the Enterprise...
Sit down, Captain.
You'd better listen to this.
Lieutenant La Forge,
status report.
LA FORGE:
The containment area
is completed, Captain
and the last of the modules
are being inserted.
Take us to warp six
as soon as possible.
Acknowledged.
This is Dr. Katherine Pulaski.
We'll handle
the formal introductions later.
Counselor Deanna Troi
is pregnant.
She...
she's going to have a baby.
A baby?
This is a surprise.
More so for me.
This pregnancy is unlike
anything I've ever encountered.
Since she came to me
a few hours ago
I have done two complete
examinations of Counselor Troi.
This is the first examination.
The fetus is about halfway
through the first trimester--
about six weeks old.
Now, understand, we believe
that conception took place
11 hours ago.
What?
PULASKI:
It gets better.
This is the second exam
one hour later.
Now it's consistent,
except for the fact
that it appears that the fetus
is several weeks older.
At this growth rate
Counselor Troi will have
her baby in about 36 hours.
The normal gestation rate
for a Betazoid is ten months.
I don't mean
to be indelicate...
... but who's
the father?
Last night, while I slept
something, which I can only
describe as a presence
entered my body.
PICARD:
A life-form of unknown
origin and intent
is breeding right now
inside Counselor Troi.
Our purpose here
is to determine
what is to be done about this.
Discussion.
Now wait.
Now, let me get
this straight.
Deanna was
impregnated by...
what?
Doctor, what do
the tests show?
Is it a humanoid?
An alien?
It's a male human.
Or in this case
half human, half Betazoid.
RIKER:
Exactly the same as Deanna.
PULASKI:
In every way.
PULASKI ( distantly ): In fact,
there is nothing to indicate
that there are any genetic
patterns other than hers.
RIKER: I don't think
this is a random occurrence.
I think there's a purpose here,
and a reason.
What? I don't know.
WORF: Captain, obviously
the pregnancy must be terminated
for the safety
of the ship and the crew.
RIKER: Worf, you can't assume
the intent was belligerent.
WORF:
That is the safest assumption.
DATA:
Captain, this is a life-form.
Not to allow it
to develop naturally
would deny us the opportunity
to study it.
WORF:
If the fetus is aborted
laboratory analysis
is still possible.
RIKER: Doctor, is there any
health risk to Counselor Troi
if the fetus is aborted?
Captain.
Do whatever you feel
is necessary
to protect the ship
and the crew, but know this--
I'm going to have this baby.
Then it seems
that the discussion is over.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have finally arrived
at 'audet IX
where we will pick up
the specimens of plasma plague
for transport to Rachelis.
It is only because
so many lives are at stake
that I'm willing to put
this ship and crew
at such great risk.
Meanwhile,
Counselor Troi's pregnancy
continues to progress
at an astonishing rate.
How are you feeling?
I should be feeling
uncomfortable
with all the changes
in my body
but I don't, I feel fine.
Better
than fine--
wonderful.
Standard orbit.
Standard orbit, sir.
Open hailing frequencies.
WORF:
Hailing frequencies open.
'audet IX, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
Ah, the Enterprise.
Here at last.
Well, good,
let's get going.
Excuse me.
To whom
am I speaking?
To whom are you speaking?
I'm Lieutenant Commander
Hester Dealt.
Medical trustee,
Federation Medical
Collection Station.
Are the specimens
ready for transfer?
Yes, but, with your permission,
I would like to inspect
the containment area
before we proceed.
Now, it's not
that I doubt
the ability of
your crew, Captain
but we cannot
afford a mistake.
I appreciate your caution.
In the like vain, I want
a complete detailed manifest
of everything you intend
to bring aboard my ship.
Very good.
I will allow you access
to my computer banks, okay?
PICARD:
Mr. Data, download
the inventory
and cross-reference it
with the medical computer.
Number One, arrange to have
Hester Dealt transported up.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Although it's been
nearly 14 hours
since we arrived
at 'audet IX
Hester Dealt has still not
completed his inspection
of the containment unit.
The transfer
will not be permitted
until he is assured
of zero growth
during our voyage.
Meanwhile, the desperate pleas
from the Rachelis System
continue.
Captain, the final manifest
has been received.
At last.
Review it with Dr. Pulaski.
I want you both to be
completely familiar with it.
Aye, sir.
Data, will you help me
get to Sick Bay?
It's time.
Oh, you bet it is.
Let's get you
to maternity.
Worf, assemble your
security team in Sick Bay.
Is that necessary?
Yes, Doctor.
Captain's orders.
Well, it's strange
to need armed guards
in a delivery room.
This way.
How frequent
are your contractions?
Very close together.
In my other
deliveries
except for a couple
the father was
always present.
Difficult
under the circumstances.
Perhaps I could serve
in that capacity?
Counselor Troi
is going to need
the comfort
of a human touch
and not the cold hand
of technology.
Doctor, I think Commander Data
will do very nicely.
Your choice.
You don't have
to do anything, Data
just be with me.
PULASKI: There's nothing
to be nervous about.
Nervous?
I find this
very interesting.
Although I understand
in technical terms
how life is formed
there is still a part
of the process which eludes me.
The child inside you--
are you able to access
his thought process?
Does he have thoughts?
You are aware of him.
Is he aware of you?
When does that
awareness begin?
It's happening.
How does it feel?
Data.
Yes?
Now!
Now?
Now... now.
Doctor! Doctor!
Doctor!
This is an impatient baby.
He's eager
to make his appearance.
Now, do you want something
for the pain?
It will in no way
diminish the experience.
I have felt no pain.
None?
No.
None at all.
PULASKI:
Have your security men
stand back.
I understand the importance
of having you here
but keep out from underfoot.
( Deanna breathing heavily )
PULASKI:
Fetal position?
NURSE:
Normal.
Fetal pulse?
137.
PULASKI:
The baby is showing healthy
respiratory movements.
Reaction of the heart
rate is good.
( panting )
The baby's doing
wonderfully, Troi.
Breathe slowly.
You're doing great.
Stay calm.
That's it, there it is.
( Troi gasps )
I've got him.
You can relax.
( baby crying )
( crying stops )
There, there, that's a good boy.
Okay.
Oh, my...
he's beautiful.
Are easy births
the norm for Betazoids?
Not according to my mother.
You can come in
the rest of the way now.
PULASKI:
There's no threat, Lieutenant.
You and your men can relax.
It's just a baby.
Thank you for allowing me
to participate.
It was remarkable.
Do you have a name?
Ian Andrew,
after my father.
Were you here
all along?
Yes.
He's beautiful, Deanna.
Just like his mother.
How do you feel?
Fine.
Wonderful.
Thank you, Doctor,
for everything.
Amazing.
Captain.
Doctor, welcome
to the Bridge.
Please sit down.
How is Counselor Troi?
Did she have a good night?
I've delivered
dozens of babies
but none like this.
There was no pain,
no trauma.
It's true.
It was effortless
for both of them.
I'm not sure of your point.
She had her baby
yesterday.
If I were to examine her now
I would not be able to tell
she had a baby
or had ever had a baby.
It was as if the incident
never happened.
Data, how long before
we begin the transfer?
Two hours,
19 minutes, sir.
Number One,
you have the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
You will accompany me,
Doctor, please.
I think it's time
I paid my respects.
( door chimes )
TROI:
Come in.
Deanna, I wanted
to see how you were
and have a look
at your...
baby.
My goodness.
How old is he?
In actuality, a day.
Yes, but...
In appearance,
almost four Earth years old.
Ian...
say hello to Captain Picard.
You mean he can talk?
Hello.
Hello, Ian.
Please don't worry.
Everything is okay.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We are faced
with two major problems--
Troi's child and the deadly
cargo we're about to take on.
In the hours since his birth
Troi's baby has continued
his rapid growth
and now appears,
physically and mentally
to be a child of eight.
Still, there is no indication
as to who he is
or why he is here.
Sick Bay,
this is the Bridge.
We are ready to begin loading.
PULASKI:
We need a little more time.
It's taking longer
than we anticipated
to categorize these specimens.
Data, look at this.
"Day-ta."
What?
My name-- it is
pronounced "day-ta."
Oh?
You called me "dah-ta."
What's the difference?
One is my name;
the other is not.
Is this possible?
With all your neural nets,
algorithms and heuristics
is there some combination
that makes up a circuit
for bruised feelings?
Possible?
I am unfamiliar
with this symbol.
It indicates
a genetically-engineered
biological life-form.
About 20% of the specimens
fall into that category.
Some eager beaver at play.
Query.
"Eager beaver"?
Well, in this case,
"eager beaver"
refers to some overachieving
genetic engineer
who, probably because of lack
of anything better to do
has forced this strain
of virus to mutate
just so he can see
how bad "bad" can get.
Captain Picard.
Picard.
I just wanted you to know
what risks we're about to take.
Go on.
If the most innocuous specimen
on the manifest list gets loose
it will destroy all life
on the Enterprise
in a matter of hours.
I understand, Doctor.
Do you have a recommendation?
Considering how desperately
this is needed, no, I don't.
I just wanted you to know
what we were carrying.
Thank you.
Commander Data, if you've
completed your review
you're needed
in Transporter Room Three.
Aye, sir.
Excuse me, Doctor.
That's all right, Data--
"day-ta," whatever.
( laughter )
It's so soft.
( puppies whining )
GIRL:
Look at his tail.
TROI:
Ian.
He's a very
tactile child.
He wants to touch
and feel everything.
It's time to go,
sweetheart.
Unbelievable.
I think he's actually grown
since you dropped him off.
I like it here, Mommy.
I thought you would.
Say thank you to Miss Gladstone
for having you
and let's go get
something to eat.
Thank you.
Bye.
COMPUTER:
Bio-transport authorization
complete.
Cargo Deck Five, we will
commence transportation
on your command.
Transporter Three,
we are ready to receive.
( controls beeping )
Mm-hmm.
Data, the first batch
is in place
and we're ready for the next.
( controls beeping )
You'll inform me
when loading is complete
and the cargo secure?
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I wanted to stop by
and see how Ian was doing.
We're doing fine.
I was just about
to get him his supper.
Do you want
your supper now, too?
Um, no, Ian, but thank you
for the invitation.
You're welcome.
Have you ever played
with puppies?
They had a litter
today in the nursery.
No, Ian.
I don't think
I've played with puppies.
You should come to the nursery
while the puppies
are still there.
Perhaps later.
Ow!
Mom!
Ow.
Here, let me see that.
That's not so bad.
My face is wet.
Is that better,
sweetheart?
Everything's
going to be fine.
He allowed himself
to be burned.
Mm-hmm,
for the experience.
Who is he?
Why is
he here?
What does
he want?
Ian, could you tell us
why you're here?
Because Mommy said
it was time to eat.
No, I mean, why are you here
on this ship?
I live here.
Ian, I think
the Captain
wants to know if you're ready
to tell us why you came here.
No, not yet.
The answer
is within him.
When his cognitive powers
are sufficiently developed
he will be able
to articulate it.
I hope he will
tell us soon.
Cargo's been loaded
and is secure.
Then take us out
of orbit, Number One.
Set a course for
Rachelis, warp six.
( inaudible )
Excuse me.
Can I get you something?
No, nothing.
I just like
to stand here.
I don't blame you.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
How about a nice cup
of Mareuvian tea?
No, nothing,
thank you.
You'll be leaving soon.
Yeah.
What do you see when
you look out there?
The Lorenze cluster
and there's Arneb
and there's
Epsilon Indi.
That's not what I mean.
I mean, when you look out there,
don't you see your future?
It will still be there.
What about a cup of nectar
direct from Prometheus?
No, nothing.
That's the third time
you've asked me.
It's what I'm
expected to do.
Don't you always do
what's expected?
I try.
Even if it's not
what you really want?
Sometimes.
Sometimes
it's more important
to consider others
before yourself.
Yes...
but sometimes the game
is to know when to consider
yourself before others--
give yourself permission
to be selfish.
( alarm sounds )
DEALT:
Something's wrong.
What is it?
Growth.
Where?
L-seven-three.
Bridge, this is
Cargo Deck Five.
Yes, La Forge?
Captain, we have a...
a malfunction
in the containment area.
How serious?
Very.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
For reasons as yet unknown
one of the deadly specimens
of plasma plague
has begun to grow.
Report, Mr. La Forge.
Captain, we've checked
everything.
There's no reason
for this to be happening.
I can't even isolate
the cause of the problem.
Come on, Data, we'd
better get down there.
Dr. Pulaski.
Yes, Captain?
They're having a little
difficulty on Cargo Deck Five.
Your presence is requested.
I'm on my way.
You never talk
about yourself.
Sure I do--
all the time.
People say
you're very old.
Oh?
And that you knew
Captain Picard
when he was
on the Stargazer.
No, I never knew
the Captain
till I came
on board.
Well, everyone's
very curious about you.
Yes, I'll bet they are.
Yeah, they, they want to
know where you're from.
And where do they say?
Well, they say
that you're
from Nova Kron
and that, uh...
PICARD: Mr. Crusher,
report to the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
Got to go.
Thanks.
For a dish of Delovian soufflé?
No, not for the soufflé.
I meant for the rest.
That's why I'm here.
Thanks.
Bye.
RIKER: Why this module
and not the others?
Computer, run diagnostic
on module L-seven-three.
COMPUTER:
All circuits functional.
LA FORGE:
Environments
as programmed.
Temperature-- 97 degrees Kelvin.
Radiation flux-- zero.
Stasis field nominal.
Everything exactly
the way it should be
right down the line.
Perhaps it is a sensor
malfunction.
Computer, inquiry--
is growth actually occurring
in module L-seven-three?
COMPUTER:
Confirmed.
Doctor, one of the
specimens is growing.
Destroy it now.
I can't.
Data, prepare
to jettison the module.
We can't do that either.
It will go into a spore
and remain
until it comes into contact
with a planet or another ship
and the results
will be disastrous.
Commander,
your attitude tells me
that no matter how bad
I think it is
it's actually worse?
This is not going to hold it.
Go on.
DEALT: The rate growth
is increasing so rapidly
within 30 minutes it's going
to push out of its module.
Within two hours, it will break
out of the containment area.
No, no, no.
It can't break through this.
Yes, it will.
Captain,
we may not be able
to get control
of this situation.
I recommend
we arrange a transfer
of all
non-essential personnel
to the saucer section.
And if we lose containment
we should be
prepared to separate.
Make it so.
Why this one specimen
and none of the others?
Something is
stimulating it.
Do you have
the etiology--
do you know how
it was developed?
Yes.
It's right over here.
It's a mutated strain
developed
by Dr. Susan Nuress
during an outbreak
of plasma plague
70 years ago
in the Oby System.
It was number nine
in a series of 58 tests.
This particular one
bombarded
by low levels
of Eichner radiation.
Could exposure to Eichner
radiation stimulate growth?
It could, but I...
I've got some.
Why didn't you detect
this before?
I don't know.
It wasn't here before.
Well, it is now.
What emits that type
of radiation?
A subspace
phase inverter.
We don't
have one.
Certain
cyanoacrylates.
Also not on this ship.
What else?
Because it's here
and we better find it.
I can feel that
some of the people
are very worried.
Yes, I feel it, too.
But don't you worry.
It's me, Mommy.
I'm the reason.
What?
It's me.
You?
Yes.
I have to leave you now
or it will be very bad
for everyone.
What are you saying?
I have to leave now.
Leave?
You're going to die.
No, you can't!
Sick Bay,
this is Counselor Troi.
I need the Doctor
in my quarters now!
Ian!
Ian, no! Ian!
It's Ian! Hurry!
PULASKI:
What happened?
Did he eat anything?
Did he fall?
No.
Commander,
the child is the source
of the unusual radiation.
Ian said he's the reason
the ship is in danger.
That analysis is correct.
I'm losing life signs.
You must save him.
( device hisses )
( device trilling )
I'm sorry.
( sobbing )
( whooshes )
( tinkling buzzing )
LA FORGE:
Commander Riker, the containment
field has... stabilized.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Then Ian was right.
He was the cause.
Apparently so.
He is a life-force entity.
When we passed each other
in space
he was curious about us
so he decided the best
way to learn was
to go though
the process.
To be born...
to live as one of us
and, in that way,
to understand us.
He never meant
any harm.
There was a moment
when you smiled.
He said, "Thank you."
I told him we will miss him.
And I will.
( door opens )
( door closes )
( sighs )
Standard station orbit,
Mr. Crusher.
Aye, sir.
Standard orbit.
Transporter Room Three,
this is the Captain.
We have arrived.
Let's make this transfer
with all deliberate speed.
Aye, sir.
I'll be glad
to be relieved
of this cargo.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
Captain...
could I see you when
you have a moment?
In my Ready Room
when your duties permit.
Thank you, sir.
How long is it
going to take
to develop
a vaccine?
We may never develop one.
Then all of this might
have been in vain?
No, let's hope not.
DATA:
Stand by to energize.
Good luck.
Data, you can lock
onto the first group
and begin transporting
on my mark.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain Picard, I've
thought about this a lot.
I want to remain
on the Enterprise.
( beeps )
Have you discussed this
with your mother?
No, sir.
Before I do that
I'd like your permission
to stay.
Wesley, it's a little more
complicated than that.
Captain
this is where
I want to be.
This is where
I feel I belong.
RIKER:
Captain, transfer complete.
We are ready to leave orbit.
Make it so, Number One.
Return to your position.
( beeps )
RIKER:
All systems secure.
Take us out of orbit,
Mr. Crusher.
Lay in a course
for the Morgana quadrant.
Yes, sir.
Ensign Crusher has requested
to remain on the Enterprise.
I'm not surprised.
How did you respond?
I haven't as yet,
Number One.
I didn't think that it was
my responsibility alone.
His remaining will create
difficulties for all of us.
Yes, indeed.
With his mother gone,
who will see to his studies?
Exactly.
Of course
that duty will fall
to Commander Data.
And who will tuck
him in at night?
Come on, Commander.
I will accept
that responsibility.
Well, we know
he'll get his sleep.
PICARD:
Well, then, that takes care
of the practical
but there's more to
growing up than that.
You know, it's my
belief, Number One
that you're best qualified
to supervise that.
You willing
to serve?
Difficult decision.
Yes, I can do that.
PICARD: Now, Mr. Crusher,
communicate with your mother
at Starfleet
Medical Headquarters.
Give her my regards
and tell her that you
have my permission
to remain on
the Enterprise.
But I will abide
by her wishes.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
I know she'll agree.
Now, you have course
and speed laid in?
Yes, sir, they are.
Then, Mr. Crusher,
engage.