You're worried.
With reason.
About Worf
or Commander Riker?
Both.
I think it is perhaps best
to be ignorant
of certain elements
of Klingon psyche.
( mysterious animal noises )
( crackling )
( growling )
Above!
Look out!
( clanging )
The exercise is over!
( snarling )
( yells )
At ease, Lieutenant!
Exit holodeck.
You do this every day?
No, Commander.
Usually my calisthenics
are more...
intense.
But those sessions are
too personal to be shared.
I'll bet they are.
Computer, program
complete. Save.
( computer beeping )
Coming, Commander?
Right behind you.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42193.6.
We're on a long reach
toward the Morgana quadrant
a section of the galaxy which
has yet to be visited
by a manned
Federation vessel.
We are using
the time to further detail
the charts of
this region.
( beeping )
There it is again, sir,
an area of blackness.
It appears, it disappears,
and then it reappears.
There's no predictable pattern,
no sequence.
On screen.
There it is.
I can't see anything.
Um...
Magnify section 285.
WESLEY:
There it is, sir.
It's... like a hole in space.
Well, we're acquainted
with the wormhole phenomenon
but this...
this appears quite different.
What do your
sensors indicate?
Nothing, sir.
Nothing?
Mr. Data, you must mean
that it's empty of matter.
There's always some
energy form at work.
Sir, our sensors
are showing this
to be the absence
of everything.
It is a void
without matter
or energy
of any kind.
Yet, this hole
has a form, Data.
It has height, width...
Perhaps.
Perhaps not, sir.
That's hardly a scientific
observation, Commander.
Captain, the most elementary and
valuable statement in science
the beginning of wisdom is
"I do not know."
I do not know
what that is, sir.
Captain, if this were any
ordinary kind of hole in space
wouldn't we be able
to see what's behind it?
Counselor?
I know what
you're asking
but I feel nothing
from it.
Data, is there any
record anywhere
of any occurrence even
vaguely similar to this?
Accessing.
Negative, sir.
There is no record of any
Federation vessel encountering
anything remotely
like this.
Indeed.
I believe we have time to take
a closer look, Number One.
Concur.
Ensign, slow down
to half-impulse power.
Adjust coordinates
to intercept this...
whatever this is.
Scanning and recording as we go.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Adjusting course to intercept
in 12 minutes.
Let's launch a probe into it.
Worf, prepare
scanner probe.
Let's see what's in there.
This is close
enough, Ensign.
Hold this position.
Aye, sir,
holding this position.
You may fire the probe
when ready, Mr. Worf.
All the probe's systems
are functioning perfectly, sir.
It's gone.
Data, what happened?
Unknown, sir.
Recommend we go
to yellow alert, sir.
Why?
Explain.
Sorry, sir, it's...
Mr. Worf
this starship operates best
when my officers share with me
what is on their minds.
My thoughts
were of an old Klingon legend
of... a gigantic,
black space creature
which was said to devour
entire vessels.
Devour vessels?
Sorry, Commander.
I agree these are thoughts
hardly worthy of a trained
and practical
Security Officer.
Mr. Worf
will you launch
another probe--
this time a class 1
with full sensor array.
Launching, sir.
Happened
even more quickly.
Recommend we fire
photon torpedo, Captain.
Negative.
Captain, based on where
the probes disappeared
I've been able to plot
the outer boundaries.
I could move
in closer.
Make it so, Mr. Crusher.
Thrusters only.
Mr. Data?
Still no readings
of any kind, sir.
Number One?
I'm going to go with Worf
on this one.
Let's be careful.
All right, that's enough,
Ensign.
Come to full stop,
and hold these coordinates.
Aye, sir.
( whoosh )
What's happened?
Data?
Whatever it is, sir,
we seem to be inside it.
RIKER:
It enveloped us.
It moved.
All stations, report.
DATA:
No response,
Captain.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
While exploring
a strange void in space
without any form
of matter or energy
we have apparently moved past
its outer boundary
and entered it.
After a brief disruption
our ship's communications
have returned to normal.
All stations
have reported, Captain.
There appears to be
no immediate threat
to the ship or the crew.
Let's hold this position
for awhile, Number One.
This is worth studying.
RIKER:
Incredible.
It's like looking
into infinity, sir.
Remember the course
in ancient history
at Starfleet Academy?
About the time when men still
believed the Earth was flat?
Mm, and that the sun
revolved around it.
And that if a ship sailed
too far out into the ocean
it would fall off
the edge of the world?
"Beyond this place
there be dragons."
It's even said that
crews threatened
to hang their captain
from the yardarm
if he refused to turn back.
I'm sure no one here
has that in mind, sir.
How comforting, Number One.
WESLEY:
Captain?
We have no communications
outside of the void.
Complete your scans, Data.
Let's not stay any longer
than we have to.
PICARD:
Hello, Doctor.
Have you been briefed
on what's happened?
I heard, but I don't
understand it, Captain.
I wish I could say I did.
Increase magnification by ten.
By 100.
PULASKI:
Isn't this
impossible, sir?
I'm not a Bridge
Officer, but...
Increase by 1,000, Mr. Data.
By 10,000.
It does know how to do
these things, doesn't it?
Commander Data knows
precisely what he is doing.
Forgive me, Mr. Data.
I'm not accustomed to working
with nonliving devices that...
Forgive me again.
Your service record says
that you are alive
and I must accept that.
Engineering.
LA FORGE:
Lieutenant,
are all your
systems functioning?
Yes, Captain.
Wherever we are
it seems to have no effect
on engineering.
Thank you,
Lieutenant. Data?
Difficult to make
a judgment, sir
based on the absence
of information.
Speculate.
This void has a total lack
of dimension.
Therefore, by any accepted
standard, it does not exist
yet being within it
denies that conclusion.
Might we have moved
into another dimension?
Could a lack of dimension
be another dimension in itself?
That's an interesting question.
Mm, yeah,
for a later discussion.
( sighs )
Number One, I think we should
get on with our mission.
Starfleet can send
a science vessel back
to investigate this further.
Move us back out of here.
Aye, sir.
Wesley,
reverse our direction.
Set a course
for the Cornelian star system.
Impulse power.
Aye, sir.
Reversing direction.
Course laid in.
Engage.
Our engines have engaged,
haven't they, Ensign?
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Lieutenant La Forge
I'd like you to monitor
our velocity closely.
Is everything all right
up there, Captain?
Are the engines
operating normally?
Yes, sir, everything looks fine
down here.
We're increasing to warp two.
Aye, sir.
We should be seeing stars
by now.
Data, how far have we come?
Inertial guidance shows
1.4 parsecs traveled, Captain.
Ensign?
Confirmed, sir.
Exactly what my readings say.
Engineering, transfer to Bridge.
What's happening, sir?
We should be clear.
We should be.
We're on a reverse course.
Full stop, helm.
WESLEY:
Full stop, sir.
According to this
we're already well
past the point
at which we
entered the void.
Except that
we are still in it, sir.
Captain...
if we dropped
a stationary beacon
and traveled straight away
from it
we would have a fixed point
of reference to confirm
speed and
distance.
Make it so, Data.
Lock onto the beacon.
Keep it dead astern.
( rhythmic chiming )
The beacon is in place, sir.
Dead ahead. Impulse power.
The beacon is falling astern,
Captain.
Engineering, report.
All systems functioning
normally, sir.
Prepare to increase to warp two.
Aye, sir.
( chiming fading,
lowering in pitch )
Captain, we are
receiving a signal
from dead ahead.
Maybe you found the
door out of this.
Closing on the
new signal, sir.
Identify.
( chiming getting louder,
rising in pitch )
Captain, it is the
stationary beacon
we just released.
We must have come
full circle, sir.
We couldn't have, sir.
I've shown us moving steadily
away from that beacon.
PICARD:
Full stop.
Hold this position
again.
( chiming stops )
( fast beeping )
Captain, sensors indicate
a disturbance in sector 1-0-8.
possibly a vessel.
Perhaps some answers at last.
On screen.
The ship is equipped
with a cloaking device.
Romulan.
WORF:
It's closing.
Shields up.
Go to red alert.
I'll be at
my duty station.
WORF:
Main viewer locked
onto coordinates.
( alarm blaring )
Arm the photon torpedoes,
Mr. Worf.
Hold for my orders.
There!
WORF:
It's uncloaking.
Direct hit, sir.
Our shields are weakening.
Warn them we'll return fire.
Transmitting.
They've armed another
full spread, sir.
Fire torpedoes.
Yeah!
Oh, that was too easy.
Captain, our sensors
show no debris
from the Romulan vessel.
Impossible.
Captain, there's another
vessel approaching
in sector 0-9-1
mark 2-6.
On screen.
PICARD:
Magnify.
It's a Federation ship,
NCC 1305-e.
It's the Yamato,
our sister ship.
The Yamato's nowhere near
this quadrant.
Open a hailing frequency, Data.
USS Enterprise
to USS Yamato.
Respond, please.
USS Enterprise
calling USS Yamato.
Respond, please,
on this frequency.
No response, Captain.
Make a full scan.
Life-support system,
engineering
and propulsion
all appear functional
but there are
no life signs, sir.
Data, can we be getting
a false reading?
Since we know nothing
of these circumstances
that is at least
conceivable, sir.
You look doubtful, sir.
Hmm?
Oh, I'm not anything
right now, Number one.
I'm just a man
who's looking for answers.
LA FORGE:
Like the rat said
"Keep the cheese.
I just want out of the trap."
Captain, request permission
to board onto the Yamato
with an away team.
Perhaps something
we could find onboard
would help us figure out
what happened.
Granted,
minimal complement.
Worf, you're with me.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We remain, like a fly in amber,
trapped in the void.
We have encountered a vessel
which appears to be
the USS Yamato.
All its systems are shown
as functioning
yet it seems devoid of life.
Commander Riker is leading
an away team.
Hopefully,
the answer lies over there.
Have you got a lock
on that other ship?
Aye, sir,
no problems at all.
Can you put us
on the Bridge?
Anywhere you say,
Commander.
I am acquainted with
the Yamato, Commander.
Recommend the aft
station of their Bridge.
When in doubt,
surprise them.
Them? Who's them?
Whoever may be there.
Our sensors indicate
no life-forms.
Still, the tactic
is sound.
Agreed.
Aft station, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Phasers on stun.
( high-pitched beeping )
Energize.
This isn't the Bridge.
Worf?
( screeching howl )
( howling )
( screaming )
Ho! Don't fire!
I heard you screaming.
I was coming
to help.
You heard me?
I heard you.
Transporter Chief,
where do you show us over here?
( staticky ):
We show...
( static fades out )
Captain, do you read me?
RIKER:
We're having difficulty
with our communications...
Number One, come in.
Transporter Room,
this is the Captain.
We're out of contact
with the away team.
Beam them back immediately.
I've lost the lock on them.
Nothing on my
communicator, sir.
Computer on.
Let's find a turbolift
to the Bridge.
Transporter Room, have you
been able to establish a lock?
COMPUTER:
Emergency power engaged.
Initiate full check,
all systems.
LA FORGE:
Engineering
section, report.
What is our situation?
Engineering?
Captain, request permission
to leave the Bridge.
Granted.
This isn't
a Federation ship.
These walls aren't tritanium.
It's close, but it's a material
beyond our technology.
Let's get to the Bridge.
There's got to be an answer
to all of this somewhere.
This Bridge should be
four decks above us.
What's going on here?
That's not where
we came from.
Wait a minute.
Two Bridges?
If we go through there,
where will we be?
On the Bridge.
But we are on the Bridge.
It's up to you, sir.
Let's see what happens.
Is it the same Bridge?
Or did we step
from one Bridge...
onto another Bridge?
( beeping )
We've regained ship's
communication, sir.
Captain,
I have a star fix.
On screen.
HASKELL:
It's an
opening, sir.
Confirm, sir,
navigation is
possible.
Should I set a course?
Transporter Room
do you have a fix
on the away team?
Negative, Captain.
Damn.
Sir!
WORF:
Commander.
How did you...?
Where did you come from?
What's going on?
A ship has one Bridge.
One Bridge!
One Riker, one Bridge!
( growling )
( speaking Klingon )
Lieutenant!
This is impossible!
Impossible!
Pull yourself together.
Worf!
( snarling )
( muttering ):
At ease, Lieutenant, at ease.
Captain, the star
fix is fading.
Data, lock onto the Yamato
with a tractor beam.
We'll leave together.
I cannot make
the lock, sir.
Captain, the star fix
is almost gone.
Let it go.
But, sir, we can get out.
TRANSPORTER CHIEF:
Bridge.
I have reestablished contact
with the away team.
Beam them back immediately.
Captain.
Come in, come in,
Enterprise.
TRANSPORTER CHIEF:
Hold position, away team.
I've got you.
We're bringing you home.
Transporter Room, hurry!
Captain, it's almost gone.
What the hell
is going on?
Are you all right,
Number One?
I've had it.
Let's put all this
technology to work
figure out
what is going on
and get the hell
out of here!
A ship that was almost
the Yamato
existing in a hole in space
with no crew aboard.
Now what is the purpose?
Add to that
an attack by a nonexistent
Romulan vessel.
It does suggest
an interesting question:
was our away team
actually over there?
If we weren't over there,
where the hell were we?
HASKELL:
Commander, I have reestablished
the star fix.
Great.
Set course.
Velocity,
warp two.
Course
and speed set.
Engage.
I've lost
contact, sir.
What?
The star fix is gone.
Captain, it is not
in the same sector
but another opening
has appeared.
All right, set a course
for those stars.
Warp 6.
Yes, sir,
warp six.
I've lost the
signal, sir.
What's going on here?
All stop.
Captain...
Yes, Mr. Data,
I can see it.
This game is now
wearing very thin.
Let's just hold
this position.
Counselor, you've
said that you sensed
no intelligence
in all of this.
You haven't changed
in that belief?
I am not certain
of that now, Captain.
I do sense
something unusual.
Perhaps a different
level of
consciousness?
Yes.
Perhaps an intelligence so vast
it eluded me.
Rats in a maze.
Exactly.
Hmm? Explain.
Well, everything
we've been through
reminds me
of a laboratory experiment.
As if something
was testing
our responses
to stimuli.
Are you suggesting...?
Are you suggesting
that we're in some
kind of laboratory?
Yes.
HASKELL:
The opening seems
closer, Captain.
I've had enough of being
led about in this way.
Agreed, Captain.
Hold present position.
Good. Don't satisfy
its curiosity.
WORF:
Captain, look!
Why are you so alarmed when
I've gone to such trouble
to look just like you?
Captain, sensors show nothing
out there.
Absolutely nothing.
Sure is a damned
ugly "nothing."
I am Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise
representing
a federation of planets
in this part of the galaxy.
Can you identify whoever
or whatever you are?
Nagilum!
Speaks right up for
something your sensors say
isn't there, Data.
We still have no idea
what you represent.
Data.
Nagilum.
You are of different
construction than the others.
Interesting.
Picard...
Riker...
Geordi...
Haskell...
What are you?
Your construction
also differs.
Oh...
My... construction?
Perhaps referring to
your gender, Doctor.
Yes, well, uh,
there are minor differences.
I'm what we call a female.
I understand.
The masculine
and the feminine.
It is the way in which
we propagate our species.
Please demonstrate
how this is accomplished.
Not likely.
Whatever you are,
your actions are not welcome.
Let me put up
the shield, sir.
Sensors still show
nothing there.
Your life-form
surprises me more and more.
Is it true you also have only
a limited existence?
Answer.
What information
do you want?
I don't understand
the question.
You exist, and then
you cease to exist.
Your minds call it "death."
( screaming )
How interesting.
( beeping )
( electronic whine )
He's gone.
We cannot allow you
to do that!
We will fight you.
To understand death
I must amass information
on every aspect of it.
Every kind of dying.
The experiment shouldn't
take more
than a third of your crew--
maybe half.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42194.7.
It is obvious
that whatever we have met
sees no value in our kind
of life-form.
How do we fight something
that both is
and is not there?
I know this much.
We are unimportant to it.
WORF:
In a battle
for survival, Captain
30 to 50% casualties...
Would be appalling.
But within
acceptable limits.
This is not a battle, Worf.
No, a laboratory
experiment would be
the closest comparison.
Is there any reason
for not believing this Nagilum?
No.
All evidence indicates
it is willing and able
to do as it proposes.
Agreed.
Under the circumstances, I think
there is only one decision.
I will not
stand by
while half my crew
is slaughtered.
Sir, I do not believe
there is anything you can do
to prevent it.
Yes, there is.
What?
Destroy the Enterprise.
Isn't that a little
like curing the disease
by killing the patient?
It's better than standing
around helplessly.
( sighs )
Why do I get the feeling
that this was not the time
to join this ship?
COMPUTER:
Recognize Picard, Jean-Luc.
Recognize Riker, William T.
Initiate auto-destruct sequence.
Does Riker, William T., concur?
I do.
Initiate auto-destruct sequence.
Desired time interval.
Stand by.
Interesting question.
How long to prepare to die?
What would be least painful
for our crew?
Move to it quickly
or allow them time
to prepare for it
thoroughly?
Well, 20 minutes--
nice round figure?
Initiate auto-destruct.
Interval...
20 minutes.
20 minutes to auto-destruct.
( rhythmic buzzing )
19 Minutes, 50 seconds.
( soft piano music plays )
( door chimes )
Come.
Our destroying ourselves
won't change its mind, Captain.
I would feel that.
You didn't mention
you were that certain.
I was wrong
not to tell you.
And your decision
may also be wrong.
( door chimes )
Yes, come in, please.
I have a question, sir.
Yes, Data, what is it?
What is death?
Oh, is that all?
Well, Data, you're asking
probably the most difficult
of all questions.
Some see it as a changing
into an indestructible form.
Forever unchanging.
They believe that the purpose
of the entire universe
is to then
maintain that form
in an Earth-like garden,
which will give delight
and pleasure
through all eternity.
On the other hand,
there are those
who hold to the idea
of our blinking
into nothingness...
( snap )
with all
of our experiences
and hopes and dreams
merely a delusion.
Which do you believe, sir?
Considering the marvelous
complexity of the universe--
its clockwork perfection
its balances
of this against that
matter, energy
gravitation,
time, dimension--
I believe that our existence
must be more
than either
of these philosophies.
That what we are
goes beyond Euclidean or other
practical measuring systems
and that our existence
is part of a reality
beyond what we understand
now as reality.
We should not let ourselves die,
Jean-Luc.
I agree with her... Jean-Luc.
TROI:
If only half
of us live
then I would rather take my
chances on being one that does.
Yes, it is wrong of you
to force us.
It is wrong.
Yes, this is very wrong.
Neither of you should
be reacting in this way.
Computer...
locate Commander Data for me.
Commander Data is on the Bridge.
It's not going to work, Nagilum.
DATA:
Captain, we are clear.
We are out of the void.
RIKER:
It's gone, Captain.
We can abort the auto-destruct.
Hold, Number One.
But, Captain...
Hold.
COMPUTER:
One minute to auto-destruct.
We are out
of the void, sir.
You may stop auto-destruct.
Mr. Crusher, warp six,
any heading.
Now.
COMPUTER:
50 seconds to auto-destruct.
( alarm wailing )
40 seconds to auto-destruct.
Captain.
It could all be part
of the illusion.
Commander Data, report.
All navigational
systems
confirm we are
at warp six, on course, sir.
Counselor Troi?
Captain
it has gone.
I no longer feel its presence.
20 seconds to auto-destruct.
Ten seconds to auto-destruct.
Captain.
Abort auto-destruct sequence.
Riker, William T.,
do you concur?
Yes, absolutely.
I do indeed concur
wholeheartedly.
Auto-destruct canceled.
A simple "yes" would have
sufficed, Number One.
I didn't want there to be any
chance of misunderstanding.
Of course.
You have the Bridge.
He sure held that bluff
to the last second.
Didn't he, sir?
Was he bluffing?
Well, Nagilum, I hope
you got what you needed.
You have provided me
with much more than I needed.
Why did you release us?
You could have seen
the way we faced death.
It wasn't necessary.
I have learned
all I needed to know.
Would you like me to share
some of my conclusions?
I'm not interested.
Oh, of course you are.
You are too inquisitive
not to want to know.
You seem to find
no tranquility in anything.
You struggle
against the inevitable.
You thrive on conflict.
You are selfish
yet you value loyalty.
You are rash, quick to judge,
slow to change.
It's amazing you've survived.
Be that as it may
as species,
we have no common ground.
You are too aggressive...
too hostile, too militant.
During this period,
you, too, have been evaluated.
It would seem that we have
at least one thing in common.
Oh?
Curiosity.
The point
is well taken, Captain.
Perhaps that is a trait
we share.
Then perhaps
we shall meet again
but, next time, it will be
out here among the stars.
Ensign, put us back on course.
Warp three.
Aye, sir, warp three.
And, Ensign, if you
encounter any holes...
steer clear.