PICARD: Captain's log,
Stardate 42286.3.
We have arrived on station
at coordinates 3629 by 584
three days early
for our rendezvous
with the USS Victory.
There is nothing to do now
but hold this position
and wait.
( indistinct chatter )
Yes, Commander?
Is there a problem?
Chief engineer La Forge
called for me, "urgent."
Oh, of course.
He's, um, over there
with the Victory.
Geordi, I've just had
a strange conversation
with your assistant.
Although it is three days
until we rendezvous
with starship Victory, she...
She believes it has
already arrived?
Not the starship, my friend.
The original.
This is my gift
to the Victory's
Captain Zimbata.
Ah, most unusual.
I served with him
as an ensign.
Sure wish he'd been
in command of this Victory.
Wind and sail.
That's the proper way
to move a ship.
But, Geordi, your
Starfleet specialty
is antimatter power,
dilithium regulators...
That's exactly why
this fascinates me, Data.
See, it's human nature
to love what we don't have.
Simpler days, huh?
Anyway, stringing this rigging
has made me dream
of handling sails...
This is not
a computer simulation?
Data, the whole point
in doing something like this
is to make it by hand.
Hmm.
Geordi, your message
said "urgent."
Ah, so it is.
While we're waiting
to rendezvous with the Victory
we have time for me
to be Watson.
More properly,
your Watson.
My Watson?
Well, I've just shown you
one of my dreams.
Now let's go and share
in one of yours.
Ah, yes.
That does seem only fair.
Clancy, I'll be
gone for awhile.
See that no one touches this.
Aye, sir, and where
can I reach you?
DATA:
He can be reached
at 221B Baker Street.
Sir?
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Computer,
select at random a mystery
by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle
in which I will
play Sherlock Holmes
and Lieutenant La Forge
will be Dr. John Watson.
Program complete.
You may enter.
Excellent.
Look at all
the detail.
So you say everything in here
has some significance?
Holmes collected
nothing--
neither trinkets
nor thoughts--
which was not specifically
significant to him.
This?
The emerald tie pin
presented to Holmes
by Queen Victoria
after he solved the
theft of the Bruce-
Partington plans.
A copy of Whitaker's Almanac,
which provided Holmes with
the key to the secret code
in "The Valley of Fear."
The snuff box
of Wilhelm Gottsreich
Sigismond von Ormstein.
LA FORGE:
All right, Data, you solve
the cases and get all the gifts.
What do I do?
Primarily,
as Dr. Watson,
you will keep
a written record
of everything
I say and do.
Hmm?
For later publication.
And the famous Holmes violin.
He purchased this
in a pawn shop
in Tottenham Court Road
for 55 shillings,
which he considered to be
a very good investment.
( plays beautifully )
GEORDI:
In the hands of some,
the violin
is a wondrous thing,
equally capable
of stirring the soul
to the heights of bliss
as to the depths of despair.
But...
Data, that's incredible.
How can you play it like that?
Merely throwing myself
into the part, Watson.
But in the hands
of my friend--
Mr. Sherlock Holmes--
the violin ceases to be
a musical instrument at all
and becomes...
DATA:
Watson...
we are about to have guests.
How could
you possibly...?
( knocking )
Be a good fellow
and answer that.
Let's not keep
the inspector waiting.
Inspector who?
Lestrade, of course.
Holmes, are you there, man?
Thank the almighty you're
available today, Holmes.
I'm in a deuce
of a dilemma.
And may I say
your perturbation
becomes you,
Inspector Lestrade,
whilst simultaneously
affording me the opportunity
to yet again
serve queen and country.
Data, Holmes really
talked like that?
Absolutely.
We need your
help, Holmes.
You see...
this gentleman here--
the emissary
of a foreign government--
has been the victim
of a most accidentally
wicked crime.
Damn.
Haven't they invented
the electric light by now?
What, dear fellow?
( clucks tongue )
Watson...
Pray continue, Inspector.
To put the matter
simply, Holmes,
this man was accosted by gypsies
intent on depriving him
of his most valuable
possessions.
And in the process of picking
his pockets clean
they also happened to bag
a photograph this
man was carrying.
Great Scott, the photograph.
I believe you will find,
Inspector, that this
emissary here works
not for but against
the King of Bohemia.
And that photograph
of the king and his mistress
is to be used for blackmail.
Further, upon deeper reflection
you will deduce, as did I...
Computer,
freeze program.
Exit.
Geordi...
Where are you going,
Geordi?
I'm done.
But...
Geordi, I was about
to reveal the fact
that the sir
is in fact a madam...
Data, what was the point
in going to the holodeck?
To solve a Sherlock
Holmes mystery.
Exactly.
But you've got them
all memorized.
The first time anyone
opens their mouth
you've got it solved.
So there's really no mystery.
If there's no mystery,
there's no game.
No game,
no fun.
Oh, I'm not upset
with you, Data, really.
It's just that we go through all
the trouble to arrange the time
to go down to the holodeck,
to get the proper wardrobe
to get into character
and then...
( snaps fingers )
Boom!
Before we even get started,
you jump to the end.
You see, I was looking
forward to the mystery.
Then I should have extended
the sequence of events?
Oh, I'm not getting through.
The fun in the program, Data,
was in the attempt
to solve a mystery.
Is that not exactly
what we were doing?
PULASKI:
You're wasting your
breath, Lieutenant.
Saying that to Data
is asking a computer
not to compute.
Am I so different
from you, Doctor?
Are you able to cease
thinking on command?
In medicine, I'm often faced
with puzzles
that I do not know
the answer to.
She's right, Data.
You always know the answer.
To feel the
thrill of victory
there has to be the
possibility of failure.
Where's the victory
in winning a battle
you can't possibly lose?
Are you suggesting
there is some value in losing?
Yes, yes, that's
the great teacher.
We humans learn more often
from a failure or a mistake
than we do from
an easy success.
But not you.
You learn by rote.
To you, all is memorization
and recitation.
LA FORGE:
Oh, I don't know
about all that.
Deductive reasoning
is one of Data's strengths.
Yes, and Holmes, too.
But Holmes understood
the human soul--
the dark flecks
that drive us
that turn the innocent
into the evil.
That understanding
is beyond Data.
Now you're just being unfair,
Doctor.
I don't think so, Lieutenant.
Your artificial friend
doesn't have a prayer
of solving a Holmes mystery
that he hasn't read.
I have read them all.
You see?
Maybe the computer could
create one in Holmes' style--
one where you wouldn't
know the outcome.
As I said,
he wouldn't have a prayer.
I accept
your challenge, Doctor.
Good for you, Data.
We shall return
to the holodeck
where I shall dare it
to defeat me.
And you, madam, are invited
to be a witness.
I wouldn't miss it.
Come, Watson.
There.
I've instructed the computer
to give us a Sherlock
Holmes-type problem,
but not one written specifically
by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.
So this will be
something new,
something created
by the computer?
Exactly.
Will that be
sufficient, Doctor?
We'll see.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
You may enter.
WOMAN:
Nice and fresh!
MAN:
Pies! Pies!
Some are meat, some are sweet!
They're lovely!
Pies! Pies!
Some are meat,
and some are sweet!
Very impressive.
Your first visit
to a holodeck, Doctor?
Well, with this level
of sophistication.
How does it work?
The real London
was hundreds
of square kilometers
in size.
This is no larger
than the holodeck, of course,
so the computer adjusts
by placing images
of more distant perspective
on the holodeck walls.
But with an image
so perfect
that you'd actually
have to touch the wall
to know it was there.
And the computer fools
you in other ways.
I say, Holmes,
where shall we head?
The theater, Rule's,
or a concert perhaps?
Stop him!
He stole my goods.
No!
It is a ruse.
This way.
What's over here, Data?
What are you doing,
Data? Tell us.
The running youth
was a ploy.
The real crime is here
and the intended victim
is that man--
Mr. Jabez Wilson, employee
of the Red-Headed League
dupe of a gang
of criminals.
I saw this plaque...
And this rope
hanging from the bell,
which enabled me to deduce
that Mr. Jabez Wilson
was headed here
to meet a most distasteful
and untimely demise...
from this!
( bell rings )
Fraud!
You didn't deduce anything.
All you did was
recognize elements
from two different
Holmes stories.
Fraud.
Reasoning, from the general
to the specific.
Is that not the very
definition of deduction?
Is that not the way
Sherlock Holmes worked?
Variations
on a theme.
Now, now do you
see my point?
All that he knows is stored
in his memory banks.
Inspiration.
Original thought.
All the true strength
of Holmes...
it's not possible
for our friend.
I'll give you credit
for your vast knowledge,
but your circuits
would just short out
if you were confronted
with a truly
original mystery.
It's elementary,
dear Data.
Now, wait a minute, Doctor.
We'll see whose
circuits short out.
Computer, arch.
Are you sure you want
to put yourself
through this, Lieutenant?
Better wilted laurels
than no laurels at all.
Computer, override
previous programming.
Okay. A program that
definitely challenges Data.
Now, it has to
deal with events
that he has no
previous knowledge of.
Computer, in the Holmesian style
create a mystery
to confound Data
with an opponent
who has the ability
to defeat him.
COMPUTER:
Define parameters of program.
What does that mean?
The computer wants to know
how far to take the game.
You mean, it's giving
you a chance to
limit your risk?
No, the parameters will be
whatever is necessary
in order to accomplish
the directive.
Create an adversary
capable of defeating Data.
( beeping )
What was that?
Lieutenant?
An odd surge
of power, sir.
It's gone now.
( dog barking )
( woman singing )
( people talking )
Interesting.
The same London...
but slightly different.
Is something wrong, Professor?
I... I feel
like a new man.
That dark fellow
there used the word
"arch" and then...
I wonder.
Arch.
What have we here?
Computer standing by.
What are you?
If you refer
to the arch you ordered
it provides computer control.
Do you wish
to input any commands?
Not at this time.
( gasping )
It's dark magic, Moriarty.
The best kind, I'm sure.
But I need information.
MAN: Here we go!
( continues indistinctly )
Data... I mean, Holmes, old boy,
what are we looking for?
For whatever finds us,
my dear Watson.
( woman screaming )
She has been abducted.
Who has?
The good doctor.
Mm, I think she's hiding.
She's going to lead you
on a wild goose chase
and then recount the story
to everyone from here
to Alpha Centauri.
Watson.
Hmm?
The doctor has been
carried away by two men.
One is tall.
The other is shorter,
left-handed,
and is employed
in a laboratory.
And how do you
know that?
One set of footfalls
is widely spaced.
The other is evenly spaced,
closer together.
Further, on the ground,
you can see the swirling scrapes
made by his left shoe
as he twists behind,
presumably to see
if he's being followed.
Left-footed
means left-handed.
The dark colorings
of the scrapes
are the leavings
of natural rubber
a type of
nonconductive sole
used by researchers
experimenting with electricity.
Finally...
there can be no argument.
The game is afoot.
Come, Watson!
( loud footsteps )
Hear that?
What do those footfalls
tell you, Watson?
That we're on the right track.
More particularly,
that our opposition does indeed
consist of two men
and that one of them is carrying
the bound-and-gagged
Dr. Pulaski.
Now, you know all of this
because you read it
in the Holmes story, right?
Not at all.
Because we do not hear
the doctor's footfalls,
we must assume that
she is being carried.
And since we do not
hear her cries for help,
we know that she is gagged.
Further, both sets of footfalls
are heavy and masculine.
One man seems to shuffle
and stumble
in an irregular pattern.
Since the ground is level,
we must conclude
that Dr. Pulaski
is struggling against one
of her captors,
sporadically knocking
him off stride.
Deduction - pure and simple.
Well, not that simple.
( loud footsteps )
Footfalls!
There they are again, Watson.
I dare say we have caught up
rather nicely with our quarry.
There should be
a doorway.
Come on.
Holmes, thank God
you're here.
Make way, please.
Make way.
Make way
for Sherlock Holmes.
It's murder, Holmes,
murder most foul.
Well, Holmes, what
do you say, man?
There is nothing here
of relevance.
I do not see how this connects
with the disappearance
of the doctor.
Doctor?
Dr. Watson is right
here, Holmes.
Dr. Kate Pulaski.
But do not concern yourself,
Inspector.
You have enough on your mind.
She was with you?
Inspector, if I may
be of assistance.
As I take note of
this... dead man
I deduce that he
was strangled.
You see, the finger
marks on his throat
indicate the cause of death
and, as there are
signs of struggle,
it's quite obvious
that the murderer
was a stranger
who attacked him
from behind.
Is that correct, Holmes?
No, look at his shoes.
He's more a convict,
released today
from Dartmoor prison.
He spent the day in a tavern
consuming large
quantities of gin
with his killer
who followed him to this very
spot, and waited over there
until the victim slipped
into a drunken stupor.
Then, out of fear,
motivated only
by self-protection
strangled him.
There is your killer,
Inspector.
( gasping )
LESTRADE:
Seize her!
And, when you check,
I believe you will find
that this poor soul
is the victim's
common-law wife
who has been dreading
the release
of this vile
and abusive man.
Holmes, the poor woman
hardly has the strength
to strangle a
man this size.
Not with her hands, no.
But with this!
When used as a garrote,
these beads will make a mark
quite similar to fingerprints.
And, my dear Watson, you will
note on the victim's throat
the marks are
too evenly spaced
to have been made
by human hands.
LESTRADE:
Astounding,
Holmes.
Not really, Inspector.
And now, for strictly personal
reasons, I must leave.
Come, Watson.
This murder does not
connect with our case.
Come on.
Hurry it up, quickly.
Data, wait.
If this murder
isn't connected
to the disappearance
of Dr. Pulaski
then the computer is running
an independent program.
Yes.
Why?
I do not know
and that is what puzzles me.
Then you don't know what's
going to happen next.
No.
Oh, that's what
I want to hear.
Where to now?
We will find
Dr. Pulaski in here.
How do you know that?
It is the only obvious choice.
Well, why is the
obvious choice
all of a sudden
the right one?
I mean, isn't this a
game of misdirection?
Not anymore.
He wants us to find him.
Who does?
The master criminal.
The man Holmes
could only defeat
at the cost of his own life
at Reichenbach Falls.
Our adversary,
my dear Watson
is none other
than professor Moriarty himself.
Now this is
getting interesting.
Well, there's nothing here
but these barrels.
And a trail
which is so well marked
that, obviously,
we are meant to follow it.
Oh, no, Data.
It's another dead end.
No, Watson,
not a dead end at all.
Hello?
What's this?
Can you see the scratches?
( squeaking )
The doctor was right.
Finally, we have
a game worth playing.
The time for games is over.
Professor Moriarty,
I presume?
How do you know that?
He is the one
worthy opponent
created by the author,
Conan Doyle.
And like the spider,
I feel the strings vibrate
whenever anyone new
chances into my web.
Welcome, my dear Holmes...
but not Holmes.
And Dr. Watson...
but not
Watson.
Data, what does he mean?
How does he know we're not
who we appear to be?
Where is Dr. Pulaski?
She's here.
She would not have
told you anything.
She has provided many answers.
Do you forget I have always been
your equal, my dear Holmes?
I have read her expressions.
What she has not said
is as important as her words.
Have you injured her?
I will if necessary.
But my mind
is crowded with images
thoughts I do not understand
yet cannot purge.
They plague me.
You and your associate
look and act so oddly.
Yet though I have never met
nor seen the like
of either of you,
I am familiar with you both.
It's very confusing.
I have felt new realities
at the edge of my consciousness
readying to break through.
Surely, Holmes,
if that's who you truly are
you, of all people, can
appreciate what I mean.
Data...
Say nothing.
I know that there is
a great power
called computer, wiser
than the oracle at Delphi.
A power which controls
all of this
and to which we can speak.
Arch.
Data, this isn't right.
A holographic image
should not be able
to call for the arch.
It has described
a great monstrous shape
on which I am like a fly
stuck on a turtle's back
adrift in a great emptiness.
What is this, Holmes?
Data.
Data, wait.
Data!
Wait!
Data.
Why does it frighten you,
Holmes?
Data.
Data, will you please
tell me what's going on?
Computer, exit.
Computer, execute
complete shutdown
of the holodeck.
Access denied.
Explain.
Override protocol
has been initiated.
It's still running.
The program didn't shut down.
We must see the captain.
Data, wait, what is it?
What's on that paper?
And why can't we shut
down the holodeck?
Data!
This.
This is impossible.
How can a character
from 1890s London
draw a picture
of the Enterprise?
Who's got control
of the computer?
He does-- Moriarty.
That is impossible.
I don't understand.
Nor do I.
Data, wait.
What about the doctor?
Is she all right in there?
No, she is
in grave danger.
Computer, why wasn't the
holodeck program terminated?
The override protocol
has been initiated.
On whose authority?
Lieutenant Geordi La Forge.
Me?
All right.
Tell me from the beginning
exactly what happened.
Well, Dr. Pulaski and I
had a discussion
about whether Data could solve
an original Holmes-type mystery.
Which you asked
the computer to provide.
Yes, with a worthy opponent.
Worthy of Holmes?
Oh, my God.
I asked...
I asked
for a Holmes-type mystery
with an opponent capable
of defeating Data.
That's got
to be it.
Merde.
Captain, I'm... I'm sorry.
I understand, Lieutenant.
Captain, this character
Moriarty--
he called for the arch.
He did what?
So... he has access
to the computer.
And perhaps our library files,
as well, sir.
That level
of information
would be necessary
in order to create
a true adversary
for me.
Theorize, Data.
What are his limits?
He is still a fictional
character, sir
originally programmed
with 19th century knowledge.
Which now has access
to 24th century knowledge.
What does he need
to make use of that?
Only time, sir.
WORF:
Sir.
I can lead a security team
to sweep the holodeck,
find the doctor,
and bring her out.
Captain, I believe that would
place the doctor at risk.
It is probable our mortality
fail-safe has been overridden.
Computer, where is Dr. Pulaski?
Dr. Pulaski is on holodeck two.
And her vital signs?
Strong and stable.
Captain, recommend we attempt
to destroy the hologram
generations themselves.
Is that possible, Geordi?
Using wave guides, I could split
a particle beam
out of the matter/antimatter
chamber and run it down
through existing conduit
into the holodeck.
If accelerated
to sufficient velocity
that would, quite literally,
wash away all present
holographic constructs--
the London buildings,
the streets, the people.
All gone.
Including Moriarty.
Dr. Pulaski?
Well, a particle beam will
tear apart human flesh as well.
Captain.
I'm sensing something
from the holodeck.
It's as if a unifying force,
or a single consciousness
is trying to bring it all
into focus.
There can be only
one explanation.
In programming Moriarty
to defeat me, not Holmes,
he had to be able to acquire
something which I possess.
What exactly?
Consciousness, sir.
Without it,
he could not defeat me.
Computer, what happened?
Attitude and stabilization
control of the Enterprise
was momentarily transferred
to holodeck two.
Data, I think it best
that you and I
should return
to the holodeck.
I will change
into my uniform, sir.
No, I will change
into some appropriate costume.
Our uniforms might pose
questions
which I'd rather he didn't ask.
It seems... that he feeds
on knowledge.
Well, let's not give
your nemesis
anymore information
than we have to.
How did you make
the room shake?
I'm not sure.
Now, dear lady, will that be
one lump or two?
Lumps, professor?
What sort of lumps?
Milk, of course?
Why not?
Mr. Computer proposes
the incredible thought
that we are all traveling
in a great vessel
of some sort.
Is that true?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
The scones are
likewise a must.
This is really quite
excellent.
Strange.
It actually pleases me
to hear you say that.
Very strange.
You know, you're beginning
to sound very different
from the Moriarty
I've read about.
You're not frightened of me?
No.
You should be.
Mr. Computer,
the arch please.
A few more questions,
Mr. Computer.
I just can't seem to remember
that last command.
Oh, well.
Sooner or later,
it'll all come to me.
But, in the meantime,
I have decided to approach
the problem
from a more familiar
perspective.
There's really no reason
why I shouldn't be able to use
some of the knowledge
from my world
to bring me closer to yours.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Of course you do, Madame.
The more you proclaim
your ignorance,
the more you try to mislead me,
the more I am onto you.
Your every silence
speaks volumes.
Good.
Then, if you know
what I'm saying
when I'm not saying anything,
what do you need me for?
Thank you for the tea
and crumpets.
I guess
I'll be going.
Where?
Back to here?
Yes.
Would you care to join me?
In time.
In time, I will
leave all of this
and join you out there.
Or is this where we
both are right now?
Right now, we are in London.
Tell me what you want from me
or allow me to leave.
Frankly, now,
I want nothing more
than what the fisherman
expects of the worm.
You, dear doctor,
will be the lure.
And this...
will be
the hook
for your captain,
Jean-Luc Picard.
Who is that?
How well you know.
Nice suit.
Thank you.
Captain, I will
be standing by
to assist you,
if needed.
You'll be a big hit
in London.
Computer, tell me, is
the program still running?
Affirmative.
You may enter.
Data, shall we go?
Gentlemen.
Open.
We don't have much time.
He's getting more control
of his environment.
Let's see if we can't beat
professor Moriarty
by giving him everything
he wants.
( woman sobbing in distance )
Obviously, he's trying
to alter the programming here.
Captain?
Tuppence.
Two pence.
It's supposed
to be good luck.
We may need some.
I'll take that coin, sir.
That's right,
and anymore you got, too.
Excuse me.
I don't think so.
I want all that money.
That's right--
I want it now.
Data.
This holographic image differs
from any I have ever seen.
Could he have
actually injured you?
It's more serious
than that.
I think the mortality
fail-safe may have
been circumvented.
He could have killed me.
( gasping ):
Let it go, Gov.
Come on, he's hurting me.
Data, let him go.
( gasping )
We will find Moriarty
this way, sir--
the warehouse.
( bookcase creaking )
Captain Picard.
You all right?
Yes, except for being
crammed full of crumpets.
I'm a civilized abductor,
Captain Picard.
Civilized, but still dangerous.
Bridge to holodeck control--
Worf.
Here, sir.
Status? Has anything changed?
No, sir.
Moriarty, you
were conjured up
in an attempt to
defeat Holmes here.
Once that attempt is
concluded-- win or lose--
your program has
run its course.
Your existence is done.
Congratulations, Professor.
I capitulate
to the better man.
Your victory, sir, is...
...is well earned.
It's gone beyond
that little game, Mr. Data.
And you'll note
I no longer call you "Holmes."
Whatever I was
when this began...
I have grown.
I am understanding
more and more...
and I am able to use
the power at my fingertips.
I can affect this vessel
and I can inflict
bodily harm on you
and on your doctor.
Yes, you can do that,
but you haven't.
I suspect you shook
this ship in order
to get my attention.
Well, now you have it.
What is it you want?
The same thing
you want for yourself--
to continue to exist.
If I destroy these
surroundings-- this vessel--
can you say that it
doesn't matter to you?
Interesting pun,
don't you think?
For matter is what I am not.
The computer has taught me
that I am made up
only of energy.
That may not be entirely
true, Professor.
This, which we
call the holodeck,
uses a principle similar
to another device
called a transporter.
( sighs )
In the year in which we
live, humans have discovered
that energy and matter
are interchangeable.
In the holodeck, energy
is converted into matter.
Thus, you have substance...
but only here.
And if I step off this holodeck?
PULASKI:
Then, Professor,
you will cease to exist.
PICARD:
You are not alive.
As I said before,
you are... only...
A holographic image.
I know.
But are you sure?
Oh, yes.
Does he have life?
He's a machine...
but is that all he is?
No. He is more.
Exactly.
Is the definition of life
"cogito, ergo sum"--
"I think, therefore I am"?
Yes, that is one
possible definition.
It is the most
important one
and, for me,
the only one that matters.
You-- or someone--
asked your computer
to program
a nefarious fictional character
from 19th century London,
and that is how I arrived,
but I am no longer
that creation.
I am no longer
that evil character.
I have changed.
I am alive...
and I am aware
of my own consciousness.
Moriarty, my responsibility
is this vessel and its crew.
I want my existence.
I want it out there...
just as you have yours.
That may not be possible.
Then you must murder me,
Captain.
I cannot give you what you want.
Because you do not know
how to convert holodeck matter
into a more permanent form?
Yes, that is so.
A pity.
What I have seen...
what I have learned...
fascinates me.
I do not want to die.
And I do not want to kill you.
Madam, I have enjoyed
your company.
Computer... arch.
( beeping )
Cancel override protocol.
Return control
of the holodeck
to main computer.
My fate is in your hands...
as perhaps it always was.
Bridge, this
is the captain.
Commander Riker here, sir.
Number one, the situation
is under control.
Aye, sir.
Moriarty, this
vessel's computer
has a vast
memory capacity.
How well I know.
You will not be
extinguished.
We will save
this program,
and hopefully
in time, when
we know enough,
bring you back in
a form which could
leave the holodeck.
Then perhaps
we'll meet again, madam.
It could be a long time.
Time won't pass for you,
but I may be an old woman.
But I'll still fill you
with crumpets, madam.
I detest long good-byes.
You have the arch.
As you wish--
a short good-bye.
Computer, save
the program of the
character Moriarty
and then...
discontinue.
Damage?
Mm. Yes, sir.
She cracked a spar when
the Enterprise was shaken
but, otherwise, I think she
weathered it quite nicely.
She's beautiful.
A wonderful testimony
to simpler times.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
It's just that...
I can't help
thinking how...
well, what else
might have happened,
all because I misspoke
a single word.
Well, soon she'll be shipshape
in Bristol fashion.
"Bristol fashion," sir?
It's an old navy phrase
meaning... "everything
in perfect order."
Hmm. Yes, sir.
As are we, Mr. La Forge.
Yes, sir.
RIKER:
Captain, starship Victory
has arrived.
On my way, number one.