Captain's Log,
Stardate 42477.2.
The Enterprise
has been diverted
to the Ramatis Star System.
It seems that both sides
of a bitter planetary conflict
have petitioned Starfleet
to transport
to their world a mediator
they have mutually selected.
Our orders
are transportation only.
No interference.
Reduce to half impulse.
Reducing velocity
to one-half impulse.
( door chimes )
Come.
Ah, Number One,
look at this.
Ever since we left
the Lima Sierra system
I have been puzzling over
how the third planet
could maintain
such an orbit
when it's theoretically
impossible.
But consider this.
There's no degeneration.
Exactly.
Why?
I haven't a clue.
Well, perhaps this facsimile
lacks the proper mass.
Perhaps.
But if this is
an accurate representation,
it could explain what happened
in that system.
Perhaps.
Well, it's not a matter
of any great moment.
Just a knot
I had to untie.
So, what do you want
to see me about?
Oh, we've arrived
at Ramatis III.
Oh, well.
Time to leave.
Standard orbit,
Mr. Crusher.
Standard orbit.
Mr. Data,
you have the Bridge.
Transporter Room 5.
I'm still a little
uncomfortable
with your leading
this away team.
This is not an away team,
Commander.
I consider this
a ceremonial function.
For me not to go could be
construed as lack of interest.
You will be careful, sir.
Oh, cluck, cluck, cluck,
Number One.
Sir?
You're being
a mother hen.
I appreciate
your concern.
Actually, I'm looking forward
to meeting this mediator.
We came a long
way to get him.
They wanted the best.
That, according to
all reports, is Riva.
If he can put an end
to all the years
of bloodletting
on those planets...
I think we should
do everything
in our power
to assist him.
Our job is not
to police the galaxies.
Isn't that my speech,
Number One?
No, of course
you're right.
We must not
get involved.
Coordinates
have been input, sir.
Have your
sensors indicated
any problem down
there, Lieutenant?
None.
But you're feeling
a certain confusion
about this
mission.
No.
Yes. I've never known you
to have such strong emotions
except when you're expecting
to do battle.
I am not expecting battle.
Then what is
bothering you?
Riva.
Ah.
Riva negotiated
several treaties
between the Klingons
and the Federation.
Before him, there was no
Klingon word for "peacemaker."
Then I can understand why
you're feeling uneasy.
PICARD:
Now, look.
This is a simple
ceremonial greeting.
Nothing more.
All right.
Aye, sir.
Energize.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain, this is the Enterprise.
We've arrived safely,
Number One,
but so far
we've been ignored.
I'll keep you informed.
I would appreciate it.
Captain.
WORF:
Sir.
Riva.
Please, come closer.
Before I start,
is there anything you need?
Food? Refreshments?
Thank you, no.
Then proceed.
Greetings from the United
Federation of Planets.
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
This is Counselor Troi.
Lieutenant Worf.
Greetings.
Welcome to Ramatis.
I have been
expecting you.
You are empathic.
Yes.
Then although you already
know my feelings toward you,
allow me put
them into words.
I am looking forward
to this journey
now more than ever,
because it gives me a chance
to be in your company.
I'm flattered.
I, too, am looking forward
to learning more about you.
There are aspects to Riva
of which we've not
been informed.
WOMAN:
Precisely.
Our way of
communicating
has developed over
the centuries,
and it's one that I
find quite harmonious.
Then Riva
the mediator...
Is deaf.
Deaf?
Born and
hope to die.
And the three of you
speak for him.
TOGETHER:
Yes.
We serve as
translators.
We convey not only
his thoughts
but his emotional
intent as well.
I am the scholar.
I represent the intellect
and speak in matters
of judgment,
philosophy, logic.
Also, I am
the dreamer--
the part that longs to see
the beauty beyond the truth,
which is always the
first duty of art.
I am the poet who...
Artists-- they tend
to ramble,
neglect the moment.
I am passion,
the libido.
I am the
anarchy of lust.
The romantic...
and the lover.
I am also the warrior--
the perfect line
which never wavers.
I am that which binds
all the others together.
I am harmony, wisdom, balance.
Remarkable.
And so, the--
WARRIOR:
Speak to me!
What?
Speak directly to me.
This unique form
of presentation
provoked this inadvertent
breach in protocol.
No insult was intended.
Then none is perceived.
I'm curious how this rare form
of communication came about.
The gene for hearing
is not present
in my planet's ruling line.
Not that unusual.
Indeed, it is similar to
the House of Hanover
on your planet Earth,
all of whom had hemophilia.
Or to the leaders
of Fendaus V
who were without limbs.
Many of our galaxy's
greatest contributors
have been similarly special.
SCHOLAR:
My chorus is so attuned,
they can hear my thoughts
and translate to you.
It is a relationship that
goes back for centuries.
Their ancestors provided the
same service to my ancestors.
Your method of
communication
is elegant and
quite beautiful.
WARRIOR:
It takes a fine mind
to realize that,
Counselor Troi.
This part of you doesn't
speak very often.
Only when the
spirit moves me.
Riva, if you're ready,
the situation on
Solais V is critical.
We should not delay.
SCHOLAR:
Very well.
With your
permission, Captain.
Make it so, Mr. Worf.
Enterprise, this is
the away team.
Seven to beam up.
TRANSPORTER CHIEF:
Commander Riker, the away team
plus four is on board.
Acknowledged.
Ensign, set your course
for Solais V.
Course is set.
Velocity warp 8.
Warp 8, aye.
Engage, Ensign.
Yes, sir.
What is this?
Riva is deaf.
These three speak for him.
Treat them
as interpreters.
Address yourselves
directly to Riva.
Now, may I present
my first officer...
SCHOLAR:
First, Captain, may I say
it is an honor
to be on board
such a fine vessel.
Now please, continue
with the introductions.
This is my first officer,
Commander Riker.
It is an honor to meet you.
Lieutenant
Commander Data.
It is a pleasure
to meet such a...
unique individual.
Thank you.
Lieutenant Geordi La Forge.
It is my pleasure
to meet you, sir.
What is that
you're wearing?
A visor-- it interprets
the electromagnetic spectrum
and then carries the readings
to my brain.
And without it,
can you see?
Without it, I'm as
blind as a stump.
Then your visor serves
the same function
as my chorus, which
interprets my thoughts
and translates them
into sound.
Yes.
And you don't resent it?
The visor or being blind?
Either.
Well, no, since they're
both a part of me
and I really like who
I am there's no reason
for me to resent
either one.
What is your position
on the ship?
I'm the chief
engineer, sir.
It's a blessing to understand
that we are special,
each in his own way.
Yes.
Yes, that's the way
I feel exactly.
I offer the hospitality
of my vessel,
and at your convenience,
there is a briefing
on the Solari wars.
If you wish, I'll have you
conducted to your quarters.
Thank you.
Perhaps, if it is
not inconvenient,
Counselor Troi could escort me,
with your permission.
This way.
What about you?
WOMAN:
At times like this,
we become an
encumbrance.
So, if you have rooms
for us...?
Lieutenant Worf
will escort you.
Riva's not what I expected.
Much of what
we do is similar.
Yes, I suppose
in a way it is.
We have both learned
how to allow people
to examine feelings
hidden deep within
their psyche.
In fact...
being with you here
now is provoking
an emotional revelation.
You mean, some emotion
buried deep within your psyche?
Well, not that deep.
Exactly what
are you feeling?
Can't you tell?
Some of it.
Well, I feel that soon,
perhaps after the briefing
by your Captain,
that you will be hungry.
And that perhaps
we could dine together
and compare experiences.
I'd like that.
As will I.
Will he be with us?
Well, until we find our own
method of communication.
I look forward to that time.
As do I.
I'm sorry, Data,
begin the briefing.
The factions on Solais V
are historical enemies.
So many have died
that both societies
are on the verge
of extinction.
Enough.
Thank you, Captain, there
is no need to continue.
The specific issues of the
conflict have no relevance.
So, none of the background
which we have provided
would be helpful
in understanding
why they continue to fight?
The portfolio
will indicate
that the conflict is over
a piece of land or wealth,
or some other
tangible asset.
But we both know
that is not the case.
They've been at war for so long,
it has become personal.
Exactly.
The basis for peace
must also be personal.
This is an historic
confrontation, correct?
The factions have been
at war for 15 centuries.
What's changed?
I do not understand
what you mean.
They have been killing
each other for a long time.
Now, they want to
talk peace.
So, something
about the situation
has recently changed.
What's the new piece
to the puzzle?
Data?
Unknown, sir.
Perhaps they have run out
of people to kill.
In any case,
whatever the reason,
peace is now
preferred,
which should make
your job easier.
Well, if not easier,
at least possible.
For now,
they are motivated.
But it doesn't matter.
I'll find something--
I always have.
Always?
To date, I have never failed.
Now, unless there is
something else...?
Um, no, this is entirely
for your benefit.
Then thank you for
your time and effort.
I believe
I have to get ready
for a dinner
appointment.
If you will excuse me...
Yes, of course.
The, uh...
The meeting
is adjourned.
Our mediator is
very self-assured.
We'll know soon enough
if he can deliver.
We're now approaching
Solais V.
Half impulse.
Slowing to
one-half impulse.
The sound of this ship
is quite remarkable.
Can't you feel it?
Yes.
It moves through my body
like a great pulse.
I've grown so accustomed to it,
I forget it's there.
It's easy to let that happen.
Sometimes we must allow the
surroundings to flow over us.
To dwell on each
separate part.
How it feels.
To allow it
to fill you.
How do we communicate?
I know you can read lips,
but I need your words...
Words...
are here on top.
What's under them...
their meaning...
...is what's important.
Yes, that's true.
We both
know...
...how to express...
important words... like...
..."dream."
"Being here
with you."
Yes.
Being here with you now
is very special to me, too.
Standard orbit.
Captain, I'm reading
laser activity on Solais V.
How concentrated
is the activity?
It is localized
but very intense.
So much for
the cease-fire.
Hailing frequencies.
I'm receiving
one side only.
This is Captain
Jean-Luc Picard,
Commander of the Federation
Starship USS Enterprise.
If you continue to
violate the cease-fire,
I will abort this mission.
You have no jurisdiction
here, Picard.
Where is Riva?
Riva is in charge
of the summit.
I command the ship
that brings him.
I will not endanger this
ship under any circumstances.
WORF: The other faction
is breaking through, sir.
Riva gave his word
we would speak to no one else.
Now, who breaks the rules?
Where is Riva?
I shall summon him.
Get Riva here.
RIKER: Counselor Troi, please
have Riva report to the Bridge.
They need you on
the Bridge. Now.
The cease-fire
has been broken.
I'm sure I can
resolve that.
Put them on the viewscreen.
Viewer on.
The quality of the transmission
is very poor.
It is sufficient.
Brothers...
your bravery as
fighters is known.
Now, you must demonstrate
courage in a new way.
Cease hostilities.
Allow us to meet.
( muttering )
( rapid beeping )
The laser fire has ceased.
For how long?
These Solari don't seem
likely candidates for peace.
I will need to see a
topographical overlay
of the battle area in order
to pick a site
for the meetings.
Then, I will need your help
in creating the proper setting.
Worf, prepare
your security team.
Yes, sir.
That's not necessary.
But it is prudent.
I prefer to arrive
with the smallest
possible complement.
We do not want to add to an
already tense situation.
If that is your
judgment, so be it.
We're here to provide whatever
service you require.
Thank you, Captain.
There.
Beam us down to that hilltop
and inform the
factions to join us.
The time for killing
has come to an end.
Phasers on stun,
Mr. Worf.
You won't need those.
I'm sure we won't.
Energize.
Yes, this will do.
It is important that
we set this up properly.
Commander?
If it is possible,
I would like
torches here...
and here.
Engineering,
this is the away team.
Yes, Commander?
RIKER: We are going to
need your help.
I thought you might.
We would like two
torches-- head high?
And what else?
A table... here.
Describe it.
Three-sided,
and if possible,
made to resemble
indigenous rock.
RIKER:
Did you read that, Geordi?
I did. That should
be no problem.
When will the
Emissaries arrive?
Well, it shouldn't be
too long.
And how long do you think
the negotiations will take?
They won't go quickly.
( rattling )
They're coming, Commander.
The first few minutes
will be very tense.
Please, stay calm,
and do not respond,
even if you are provoked.
We'll do our best.
( whispering )
Who is Riva?
I am Riva.
( snarling )
( grunting )
Be at ease.
I commend you both.
To come here
proves not only
your courage,
but your wisdom.
Please, give this
conference a chance.
I have no magic.
You have been fighting
all your lives.
You have known only...
No! No, never!
Never! Death first!
Riva!
Death!
Don't! Traitor!
No, wait.
Wait.
RIKER: Away team
to Enterprise.
Beam us up now.
His words are not mine.
Please, Riva.
We need you.
We need you!
How did this happen?
RIKER:
A total surprise.
Apparently a member
of one of the factions
didn't like the
idea of peace.
I don't understand what
you're trying to say.
Counselor.
Riva, go slowly.
Slowly.
Can you write it out?
I am so sorry that your
friends were killed.
I'm sorry,
I-I don't know
what you are
trying to tell me.
We have to find some way
to communicate with him.
Data, he knows some kind
of gestural language.
Find out which one
and learn it.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
Counselor, take
him to Sick Bay.
Maybe Pulaski can help.
Listen to me!
You are not alone!
Do you understand?
We are all in this
together... now.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We are monitoring increased
military activity on Solais V.
I fear that without Riva
we will be unable
to keep the Solari
from destroying themselves.
How's it going?
I have eliminated
all but five
distinct forms
of signing.
I will learn them all.
Computer, show me
gestural language
designation M-9.
WORF:
Very interesting.
A technique
of communication
that is both silent
and covert.
It could be
very useful.
The use of gestures
and hand signals
predates the spoken word
in most cultures--
the major exception being
the Leyrons of Malkus IX,
who actually developed a
written language first.
Computer,
continue presentation.
Increase.
( door chimes )
Come.
How's our mediator?
The same.
He's withdrawn.
He's very frightened.
All of his life
he's been in control,
and now, for the
first time,
he doesn't have any answers.
The doctor gave him
a complete medical examination.
His condition is hereditary.
His brain can't receive
auditory information.
So, all the prosthetics
and surgical techniques
I can use
wouldn't work.
I don't know what we can do
to help him.
I can't do anything.
It's up to him,
and he's stopped cooperating.
Counselor,
couldn't you...?
Confidence is faith in oneself.
It can't easily be
given by another.
Huh.
You're right, of course.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain, I have
reviewed and stored
five distinct
signing languages.
Here is an example
of the first.
This is blue.
This is the blue ocean.
This is the blue ocean
at sunset.
This is two people
walking along the beach by
the blue ocean at sunset.
This is two happy
people in love
walking along the beach
by the blue ocean
at sunset.
This is two pe--
Enough.
Let's talk to Riva.
Riva.
Riva, Commander Data has
learned your sign language.
Talk to us.
DATA:
It was my fault.
I am responsible
for their deaths.
In my arrogance,
I thought no one
could possibly harm
the great Riva.
I am such a fool.
You are not to blame.
What happened
appears to have been
the work of one
desperate man.
It may not reflect the
feelings of the others.
DATA: They were more
than my interpreters.
They were also
my friends.
They were a part of me.
I did not realize
how much a part...
until now.
We have been contacted
by the factions
on Solais.
They want to
renew negotiations.
DATA: I cannot.
I will not.
Don't turn away.
You have a chance
to make some good
come out of
this tragedy.
This could be the catalyst
which binds them together.
Someone else will have to
speak with them, not me.
Not after what
I allowed to happen.
How could I?
But Data
understands you.
Use him, let him
explain your words.
When Data speaks for me,
can you hear my-my
anguish, my despair?
Data is a fine machine,
but he cannot take
the place of my chorus.
It took years to develop
a communication.
That cannot be
easily replaced.
The Solari need you.
I cannot help them.
Captain, please take
me back to Ramatis.
That is regrettable.
A lot more people
are going to die.
It's possible to
install optical devices
which look like
normal eyes
and would
still give you
about the same
visual range
as the visor.
Done?
You say almost.
How much reduction?
20%.
Hmm.
There's another option.
I could attempt
to regenerate
your optic nerve,
and with the help
of the replicator,
fashion normal eyes.
You would see
like everyone else.
Wait a minute, I was told
that wasn't possible.
I've done it twice
in situations somewhat
similar to yours.
Geordi, it would eliminate
the constant pain
you are under.
Why are you hesitating?
Well, when I
came to see you,
it was to talk about
modifying this.
And now, you're saying
it could be possible
for me to have
normal vision?
Yes.
I don't know.
I'd be giving up a lot.
There's something else
you must know.
This is a one-shot.
If you decide to
change your mind,
there's no going back.
And there are risks.
I can offer choices,
not guarantees.
Well...
this, uh... this is
a lot to think about.
I'll, uh, I'll get
back to you, Doctor.
Thank you.
Captain is going to take
you back to Ramatis.
But first, he's
given me permission
to attempt to settle
the conflict
down on Solais.
Yes.
We've come so far and
paid such a terrible price.
I must try.
Help me.
DATA:
You would be better off
without my help.
I have never attempted
anything like this before.
When dealing
with two factions
so diametrically
opposed,
so entrenched
in their positions,
where do you start?
You want to know if I had
some special technique?
I want to know anything you
can tell me which could help.
DATA: There is
no... no trick.
I had no magic.
What about your chorus?
DATA: Yes, my chorus
was special.
They allowed me to combine
different perceptions.
So, there was a trick.
DATA:
Not really.
My technique
was to look for some thing,
no matter...
no matter how small,
that was common to both groups
and then to begin a process
where one person or one group
expresses themselves
to each other.
That's very hard
to accomplish.
Yes.
But what is even
more difficult
is to get each
side to listen--
really listen to
each other--
and to understand.
This isn't going to be
easy for me.
You are very good with people.
But what I do
is different.
DATA: The real
secret is turning
disadvantage
into advantage.
Why can't you do that?
Why can't you turn
your disadvantage
into an advantage?
DATA:
That is interesting.
That would give them
something in common.
I do not understand,
Counselor.
To what is he referring?
Thank you.
Thank me? Ah.
I will have the Captain
contact them down on the planet
and tell them to prepare
for your return.
There are no life signs
in the immediate area.
All right, stay sharp.
We may have to get out of there
in a hurry.
Set phasers on stun.
Energize.
The area is clear,
Commander.
Put the table over there.
Engineering,
this is Commander Riker.
LA FORGE:
Go ahead, sir.
You can beam the table
and torches down now.
Light the torches
to let them know
that I am back.
It may be quite a while
before the Emissaries arrive.
They'll be more cautious
after the last incident.
DATA: You may leave
whenever you choose.
I will send out a message
when I am ready to go.
Deanna, I don't understand
what he's going to do.
How can he mediate
without his interpreters?
He won't even be able
to talk to them.
Riva is going to teach
them sign language.
DATA:
Yes.
It is turning
a disadvantage
into an advantage.
Learning sign
will be a part
of their process
of learning how to live
together in peace.
While they are learning how
to communicate with Riva,
they'll be learning how to
communicate with each other.
DATA: And that is the first
and most important aspect
of any relationship.
Counselor, it took me only
moments to learn sign language.
It will take
them months.
Time well spent.
DATA: These people have been
fighting all of their lives.
They know only hatred,
suspicion and fear.
Even with my chorus,
I could not have changed
their attitudes in a day.
We have a chance.
They want these talks
to be successful.
Well, I am still
not comfortable
leaving you here alone.
DATA: Thank you
for your concern.
I will be fine.
And thank you...
for everything.
Enterprise, four to beam up.
Good luck.
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 42479.3.
We leave the Solais system
confident that Riva
will help the Solari
achieve a lasting peace.
WESLEY: Coordinates set,
Commander.
Take us out of orbit.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to see me?
Yes.
You read me
well enough
to sense how I
feel about you
and what you do
on this ship.
But I just wanted
to say the words.
Thank you.
Well done.