PULASKI:
Medical Log, Stardate 42437.5.
Ira Graves is arguably
the greatest human mind
in the universe.
For years, he's lived
in near isolation
on a remote planet, devoting
full time to his research.
Eight hours ago, we monitored
a message from his assistant
urgently requesting
medical aid.
I only hope
we can reach him in time.
Any response from
Gravesworld, Mr. Worf?
Nothing, sir.
Not since
their initial communication.
They send out a plea for help
and then they
cut off transmission
so they can't tell
if there's any help on the way.
That doesn't make
much sense, does it?
Ensign, what's our
ETA at the planet?
36 minutes
to orbit, sir.
Starfleet Command considers
that Graves's work
on molecular cybernetics
is reaching
a critical stage.
They consider this
a Priority One action.
A man is ill, Captain.
Treating him is
my priority one
regardless of who he is.
Did Data say why
he wants to see us?
He said something
about his new image.
I tell you, he's been acting
kind of strange lately.
How so?
Well, if I didn't
know better
I'd say he was showing
signs of insecurity.
( laughing )
Yes, but you do know better.
Androids don't feel
such things.
I don't know.
Sometimes, I think he's
becoming more human
than any of us realize.
( door chimes )
DATA:
Come in.
Data?
Geordi?
Is Counselor
Troi with you?
Yes, I'm here, Data.
Geordi said
you wanted to see us.
Indeed.
Or stated more
correctly
I wanted you
to see me.
Can we come in?
Please.
Did you damage
your face, Data?
It is a beard, Geordi.
A fine, full,
dignified beard.
One which commands respect
and projects thoughtfulness
and dignity.
Well? Opinions?
Uh...
It's, uh...
very different.
When I stroke
the beard thusly
do I not appear more...
intellectual?
( stifled laugh )
I'm sorry,
I have to go now.
Good-bye.
( laughing )
Why was she laughing?
We are receiving a transmission
from Gravesworld, sir.
It's unfocused--
not directed specifically at us.
On viewer,
Mr. Worf.
WOMAN:
If anyone can hear me
please send a doctor.
Things are getting worse.
PICARD:
Try and raise her, Mr. Crusher.
Tell them
we're only minutes away.
It's no good, sir.
I don't believe
they're receiving us.
Our records show
that she and Graves
are the only ones living
on the planet, Captain.
Then what scared her?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain,
I am picking up another signal
but it is not from the planet.
On screen, Mr. Worf.
The signal is
very weak, sir.
Audio only.
Pipe it through.
MAN:
Mayday! Mayday!
( static ):
This is the USS...
requesting emergency...
The outer hull is breached
and environmental systems
compromised.
...immediate assistance.
WESLEY:
Captain, I show
the Constantinople
in that general vicinity.
She's a transport ship
used to ferry settlers.
I'm showing 2,012
colonists aboard.
Outer hull breach-- she must
have had an internal explosion.
PULASKI:
If that's the case
they'll all be prone
to severe hypoxia.
Their lives are at risk.
We've got
to help them.
And what about Graves?
He is one man.
Suggestion, Captain.
Why don't we execute
a long-range transport
of an away team
to assist Dr. Graves
at your earliest
possible moment.
We'll come out of warp just long
enough to energize the beam.
A touch-and-go downwarping.
Ensign Crusher,
prepare to make it so.
Aye, sir.
Engineering, Mr. La Forge.
We're going to execute
a near-warp transport.
This may be a little tricky.
I would like you to handle it.
Yes, Captain.
I'm on my way.
Assemble an away team,
Number One.
Include whoever
the Doctor requires
to assist her.
Excuse me, sir, but there may be
hundreds on the Constantinople
that require
emergency attention.
I should be there
to supervise.
All right, who will replace you?
Lieutenant Selar.
She has my complete
confidence.
Worf, let's go.
RIKER:
Phaser on stun, Mr. Worf.
We don't know what's
going on down there.
There's no need
to take any chances.
Agreed, sir.
LA FORGE:
Now, remember
this is a near-warp transport,
so the effects
may be a little unusual.
What do you mean?
RIKER:
You'll see, Counselor.
Energize.
TROI:
Wait a minute.
I don't understand.
You do now.
This might sound crazy
but, for a moment, I thought
I was stuck in that wall.
For a moment, you were.
Data to Enterprise.
PICARD:
I read you, Commander.
Go ahead.
We are inside Graves's home.
All is quiet so far.
Of course, no one knew
we were coming.
Use caution, but protect
Graves's health at all costs.
Understood, sir.
I suggest we look around
to see if anyone is home.
WORF:
No need, Commander.
You heard me.
Thank God.
I'm Kareen Brianon,
Dr. Graves's assistant.
We're from a ship
called the Enterprise.
We monitored
your distress call
but then you never
acknowledged
our response.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't take the chance.
Chance?
What chance?
The chance that I might find out
someone was coming.
Kareen knew full well
that I would not be pleased,
to put it mildly.
I had no choice.
I refuse to stand by
and watch you deteriorate.
What symptoms
have you noticed?
He has pain, shortness
of breath, irritability...
Ridiculous!
I am as healthy
as a Rigellian ox.
He is not himself,
believe me.
His temper is completely
out of control.
Nonsense!
Ira.
I am a doctor.
Lieutenant Selar.
Ah, no offense, but I don't want
you touching me in any way.
It's no secret
that I don't like people much
and I like doctors even less.
That's funny.
I thought most doctors
were people.
Then you're wrong.
Ask any patient.
Though uh, huh,
I will admit, for a doctor
you're not
a bad-looking woman.
Well, well, well,
what have we got here?
Another lovely specimen
of womanhood.
I thought
you didn't like people.
Women aren't people.
They're women.
I'm Deanna Troi.
It's an honor to meet you,
Dr. Graves.
Yes, of course it is.
This is one of the truly
great moments of your life.
Excuse me, sir.
Are you a Romulan?
Hardly.
He's a Klingon, Kareen.
Kareen has lived here
since her father died
when she was very young.
Her only knowledge
of unhuman races
comes from me.
Klingons and Romulans
don't look much
alike, Kareen,
even though they
act much alike.
( growls )
Do I have
to stand here
and be insulted?
No insult intended,
Mr. Klingon.
You see, Doctor,
there's nothing wrong
with my hearing.
( stifled groan )
My, my, my, my, my...
Lieutenant Commander
Data...
Shh.
Absolutely no aesthetic value
whatsoever.
Looks like Soong's work.
Quite correct, sir.
Did you know Dr. Soong?
Know him? I taught him
everything he knows.
You could say that I was
the father of his work.
( laughing )
Which, uh, kind of makes
me your grandfather
doesn't it,
sonny?
Damn doctors!
Always sneaking up on one.
Attacking
from the rear.
Go on, gorgeous.
Spit it out.
Whatever the hell
it is, I can take it.
I've checked twice
to make certain.
You have Darnay's disease.
I'm sorry,
Dr. Graves.
It's in its final stage.
Can't you do something for him?
In all cases,
Darnay's is terminal.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42437.7.
We've successfully repaired the
stricken liner Constantinople.
46 of her people suffered
injuries, mostly minor.
They have been treated
and supplied
with the proper medicines.
Our task complete, we are
heading back to Gravesworld
with great dispatch.
( whistling
"If I Only Had a Heart" )
( coughing )
( continues whistling )
I have noticed, Doctor...
Call me
grandpa.
( coughing )
Seems more touching
in my final hours.
I have noticed, Grandpa,
that you keep repeating
the same notes of a musical
phrase I am unfamiliar with.
Oh, it's, uh, it's
ancient little tune
called "If I Only Had a Heart"
a plaintive lament
sung by a mechanical man
who longs
to be human.
It's his only wish.
What happens to this man?
He finds out
he's human after all,
always was.
Just worried so much, he...
he never realized it.
Hmm, a happy ending.
The mechanical man gets
his wish.
Stories often have
happy endings.
It's life that throws you
for a loop.
It must be so
hard for you
to be so close to being human
and yet never really knowing
what it's like to know pain.
But...
pain is unpleasant, is it not?
Pain.
Lust.
Envy.
Pleasure.
Desire.
Do you know what desire is,
Data?
Desire?
To long for, to crave,
a wish, a request...
Do you know what desire is?
No.
I do not suppose
I will ever really know.
Oh, I feel pity for you.
Your existence must be a kind
of walking purgatory--
neither dead
nor alive
never really feeling anything.
Just existing.
( stifles cough )
Oh, listen to me.
A dying man takes the time
to mourn a man
who will never know death.
Funny, isn't it?
Funny?
I have had great difficulty
determining what funny is.
I've had the same difficulty
most of my life.
We're much alike.
I'd say he has a week,
but that's only an estimate.
We do know that the disease
attacks the brain
and nervous system.
We can expect more
of the erratic behavior
of the kind
you've been noticing.
His feelings towards you
are very warm.
He's attracted to you
in many ways.
Attracted?
I know I've felt certain
feelings from him
and for him.
Had I been older
perhaps we could
have been...
but that's not the
way it worked out.
And now, it's like he's
afraid to face me.
The only one he talks to
is your friend, Data.
You mentioned
your impending death, Grandpa.
May I say
you face it
with remarkable courage
and stoicism.
Well, that is because
I'm an incredible man
possessing an iron will
and nerves of steel--
two traits that
have helped me
become the genius
I am today
as well as
the lady-killer
I was in days
gone by.
You condone homicide, sir?
It's an expression, Data.
It means I was once as beautiful
as I am smart.
Really, Grandpa?
No, not really.
But, what the hell, I'm dying.
I can remember my life
any way I want.
But I'll let you into
a little secret, sonny.
I don't really believe
I will be dying.
But the doctor...
Oh, I'll die.
But I won't
really be dead.
You see, I believe
I've learned
to transfer the wealth
of my knowledge
into a computer.
Before I die
I plan
to transfer
my great intellect
into this machine
thus cheating the Grim Reaper
of his greatest prize.
But what would you
know of death?
It is a subject forever alien
to you.
That is not necessarily true,
Grandpa.
I do have an "off button,"
if you will.
Its activation robs me
of my consciousness
therefore,
rendering me dead
for all intents
and purposes.
It is not something
I enjoy contemplating.
Oh, I can
understand that.
Just where would Soong
position such a device?
Don't tell me.
Let me guess.
PICARD:
Captain to away team.
We're standing by.
I do not wish to interrupt
Data and the Doctor.
They seem to have developed
a genuine rapport
but the Enterprise
has reached its orbit
and I'd like to
transport Graves
to the ship as
soon as possible.
( door opens )
That will not be necessary,
Doctor.
He is gone.
Gone?
It happened just
a few moments ago in my arms.
Ira Graves is dead.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I leave Gravesworld
with an empty feeling
in the knowledge that
our mission was unsuccessful.
Whatever scientific secrets
Ira Graves was about to unlock
have been lost forever.
Our immediate priority is
to reach the nearest Starbase
so that Graves's assistant
can get on with her life.
Why didn't you contact Dr. Selar
when you saw that he was
beginning to... to go?
To do so would have
been pointless.
All things must pass.
May I go now, sir?
Yes, of course.
We will try to honor him
in the manner in which
he specified, will we not, sir?
I said we would, Data.
I am glad, sir.
It was his dying wish.
Hello, Data.
It's good to
see you again.
KAREEN:
The stars are so
beautiful from space.
You always did love the sky.
A stargazer--
that is what you are.
Did Ira tell you that?
I guess he's right.
I used to spend hours just
lying on a hill looking up.
Ira never told you
how beautiful you were to him.
He never told
you that, did he?
He could not tell you.
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
But he wanted to...
every waking moment.
And he wanted you
to know that.
You were everything to him.
PICARD:
He was a fine man
a man of rare gifts
and great accomplishments.
He will be sorely missed.
Does anyone else have
anything to say?
I believe I have
a few words to say, sir.
Just look at that face.
The face of a thinker,
a warrior,
a man...
for all seasons.
Yes, Ira Graves
was all that
and more
but he was
not perfect.
Perhaps his greatest flaw
was that he was too selfless.
He cared too much
for his fellow man
with nary a thought
for himself.
A man of limitless
accomplishments
and unbridled modesty.
I can safely say
that to know him
was to love him.
And to love him
was to know him.
Those who knew him
loved him
while those
who did not know him
loved him from afar.
Data...
I am almost finished, sir.
You are finished, Data.
We now commit the body
of Ira Graves
to the timeless depths of space.
I am sorry, sir.
Perhaps it was my admiration
for Grandpa
that got the best of me.
Grandpa?
That is the way
I think of him, sir.
My only living relative
no longer living.
Data...
I was only trying
to carry out his wishes, sir.
I just wanted to keep
my promise to him.
I know that, Data.
Look, I realize
you've been studying
the human equation
with great alacrity
but perhaps you've been
working at it too much.
Don't try so hard to be human.
Just be yourself.
All right?
Yes, sir.
I will work on staying
within myself.
Grand.
You're dismissed, Mr. Data.
Thank you, sir.
( whistling
"If I Only Had a Heart" )
Captain's Personal Log.
Although Commander Data
has assured me
that his odd behavior
will return to normal,
I can't help thinking
that something went wrong
during his visit
to Gravesworld.
I'm still
concerned, Captain.
I've never seen
him act like this.
Could it be
that grandfather analogy
that Graves planted
in his head?
Data is an orphan,
in a manner of speaking.
Is it possible
that the loss of Graves
might have affected him?
Touched him
on some emotional level
we didn't know
he possessed?
I hope you're right.
I hope that's
all it is.
That was a great speech, Data.
"To know him is to love him
is to know him."
Verbal composition
at its most
sophisticated level.
Your childlike mind
cannot appreciate
the timeworn wisdom
of my words.
Childlike mind?
When you get
to be my age
you will understand.
Your age?
Data, chronologically
you're not much
older than I am.
Well, you are only
as old as you feel.
Try to remember that, boy.
You're not turning
into a philosopher
are you, Mr. Data?
I am many things:
scholar,
artist,
philosopher,
lover, genius.
Data, what's wrong
with you?
KAREEN:
Wow, how beautiful.
PICARD:
I thought you might enjoy
the Bridge, Miss Brianon.
I'm aware of your
interest in science.
Perhaps you'd like
to see the computer...
Yes, and I am aware
of your interest in her.
What was that,
Commander?
Nothing, sir.
Nothing at all.
These are the
science stations.
PICARD:
From the Command Center here
we have control
of all of the science stations.
Data, what are you doing?
I detest hypocrisy.
I wish they would just
come out and admit it.
Admit what, Mr. Data?
That your interest in Kareen
is not purely professional.
Try as
you will
you cannot win her heart.
She does not care
for older men
or men of limited intellect.
Mr. Data, you will come
with me right now.
Do you understand me?
I understand.
I understand
all too well.
Removing the competition
will not help you, Picard.
Excuse me.
Do you know
what that was all about?
Jealousy.
Intense, burning jealousy.
A human emotion,
and it was coming from Data.
If you wish to apologize,
I am prepared to listen.
You expect me
to apologize to you?
You were a bit
rude to me.
Might make you
feel better
if you said
you were sorry.
Data, something has obviously
gone wrong with your circuitry.
That is ridiculous.
I am as healthy
as a Rigellian ox.
I wish I could
believe that.
I would accompany you
to Sick Bay
but I doubt if that
would do us any good.
Sick Bay?
Are you ill,
Captain?
I'm getting there.
I'm going to have Engineering
run a full physical on you.
I am sure that will not
be necessary, Captain.
I am fully capable of running
a circuit check on myself.
It will immediately
determine any abnormalities.
Do it.
That's an order.
Just as I expected.
I am fine.
Could not be better.
For the first time
since I've known you,
I don't believe you.
Try and hold still,
will you, Data?
Data, will you wait
for me in the corridor?
Why should I?
This concerns me more
than it does any of you.
You will wait for me
in the corridor.
His insubordination is growing
by leaps and bounds.
I could use discipline,
but I'd rather
try and help him.
Well, I wish I knew
what to suggest.
I'll be damned if I can find
a thing wrong with him.
Perhaps we're looking
in the wrong place.
Meaning?
Well, if Data's
physical health
is unimpaired
perhaps his mental health
needs to be addressed.
What, are you saying that
Data's losing his mind?
With your permission, Captain,
there is one way to find out.
Now, Data,
you remember
the psychotronic
stability examination.
We all had
to take it
before graduating
from the academy.
It was a waste of time then,
and it is a waste of time now.
It will just gauge your
psychological reactions
to the images
it projects.
Mm-hmm.
Watch the screen
and let your
mind go blank.
The device
will do the rest.
( beeping )
( beeping increasing in speed)
( engines roaring )
It's safe to say
that you're his best friend.
Is it possible to speculate
about what's happening to him?
Well, sir,
it's just a guess
but, sometimes,
he wants to be human
so badly
he can taste it.
I think he just tends
to get confused
when his human
qualities surface.
Mm. Go on.
Uh, witnessing
Graves's death
may have been
some sort of catalyst
for the way he...
I have the results
of the tests.
I ran them several times
to be sure.
To be sure of what?
There are two disparate
personalities
within Lieutenant
Commander Data--
each distinctly
different--
a dominant
and a recessive.
But he's an android,
is that possible?
It must be.
The dominant personality
is unstable.
Brilliant, but vain.
Sensitive,
yet paranoid.
And I believe it is prone
to irrationality.
Of course...
Sir?
Nothing. Go on.
It seems to have an especially
strong hatred of you, Captain.
Or to a lesser degree,
any authority figure.
And the worst part is
it's growing.
How do you mean?
The alien persona
is getting stronger
and gobbling up what is left
of the weaker ego:
the Data we know.
If something isn't done
to stop it immediately
we will lose our Data forever.
Captain's Personal Log.
We have arrived
at Starbase Six
where Miss Brianon will await
transport back to Earth.
I'm greatly troubled
by the unusual behavior
of Commander Data
and fear that somehow
it is directly related
to the experiments
of Ira Graves.
Where is Data now?
He should be
in his quarters.
You ordered him
not to leave.
Tell me, where is
Lieutenant Commander Data?
Current location:
Ten-Forward.
Lieutenant Worf
will you go to Ten-Forward
and keep an eye on Data?
Don't interfere
with his actions
unless you hear
otherwise from me.
Worf here, sir.
Acknowledged.
I want to know
more about what happened
down on Gravesworld.
Lieutenant Selar
report to the Captain's
Ready Room.
Hello, Kareen.
Don't you think it's time
we stopped pretending?
You know who I am.
You're Data.
You do know who I am.
Ira?
It is me.
I am here.
I am alive.
How?
I deactivated Data
and transferred my mind
into his frame.
I never imagined
how much of my...
myself I would retain.
My feelings.
My dreams.
They won't let you
get away with it.
They'll try to stop you.
How can they?
It is my body now.
It is out of their hands.
Doctor, tell me,
how much time
did Data and Graves
spend together?
They were together
practically
the entire time
we were on the planet.
Always alone?
Yes. Always.
Doctor, what was your impression
of Graves?
He seemed brilliant,
egocentric, arrogant,
chauvinistic...
Sound familiar?
Something wonderful
has happened.
I can take a deep breath now
without feeling
stabbing pain.
I will never have
to face death again.
Think of the things
I will accomplish
over the next thousand years.
What?
Oh, I know what
you are thinking.
There is no need
to worry.
I will create an android
body for you, too.
We can witness
the end of time together.
Why are you crying, Kareen?
I can love you now.
The way I always
wanted to.
It was not right before.
I was too old for you...
too weak.
Now I can be everything
you want me to be.
I won't let you
put me in a machine.
I want to
live my life.
I won't let you
take it away from me.
Ira, Ira,
you're hurting me.
Worf to Captain Picard.
Commander Data
has left Ten-Forward.
Should I follow?
Negative.
I'll handle
this myself.
He was an expert
in cybernetics.
Yes.
Our memorial service
may have been premature.
What an achievement.
So long as men can breathe
or eyes can see
so long
lives this.
And this gives life to thee.
He was working
on bridging the gap
between man and machine.
It seems he built that bridge.
I may be forced
to tear it down.
I can hear you coming, Captain.
My ears are better than
the average dog's, you know.
I know who you are
and what you've done.
Of course you do.
I came here to talk to Data.
Hmm-mm.
I cannot allow that.
I understand your desperation--
the shock of learning
you were dying--
but you have no right
to do what you've done.
I have every right, Captain.
I am man,
he is machine.
There is
no question
who must live
and what must die.
What of Data?
( chuckling )
Data?
Before me, he was nothing.
Just a walking
tin can
with circuits
for intestines.
Pathetic.
Without heart,
a man is meaningless.
I would not come up here
if I were you, Captain.
I might not like it.
DATA:
You are most fortunate,
my dear Captain
that I am not a violent man.
Not a violent man?
This... this is not my fault.
They told me I was not
supposed to be up here.
They should not
have done that.
Graves,
listen to me.
No one can deny the significance
of your transformation...
but I don't believe that
this was part of your plan.
Encountering Data
was mere coincidence--
one that offered you more
than you could have dreamed--
but something has gone wrong.
Look here.
Graves, this experiment
must be terminated.
This is idiotic.
Picard to Sick Bay.
PULASKI:
Yes, Captain.
How is Miss
Brianon?
Her left hand is fractured
in two places.
We've just begun treatment.
I'm afraid there are two
more injuries in Engineering.
I'm on my way.
Who's next?
These were all accidents.
I did not intend...
How many more
accidents?
You must leave this body.
No. I live here now.
Graves, every man has his time.
Every man.
Without exception.
But you've
cheated.
You have extended your life
at the expense of another.
Graves, give Data back.
Give him back.
Data is dead.
No.
He must not be lost.
He's not simply
an android.
He's a life-form.
Entirely unique.
Data is not human.
He is...
He is
different, yes.
But that does not
make him expendable
or any less significant.
No being is so important
that he can usurp
the rights of another.
Now set him free.
No!
How many...
how many more accidents?
Data-- where is he?
Just take it easy, Captain.
We can't afford to
take it easy, Doctor.
Tell me, where is
Lieutenant Commander Data?
Data?
Data!
Data, can you hear me?
Geordi.
Yeah.
May I ask a question?
I think you just did.
Quite correct.
Then may I ask another question
after this one?
You can ask me
anything you want.
Why am I lying
on the floor
in this
undignified position
with the four of you
standing over me
displaying expressions
of conc...
I've heard more
than enough.
You're you again.
KAREEN:
Captain...
Captain, look at this.
He's in there.
Ira put himself
in the computer.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've said good-bye
to Kareen Brianon
with the hopeful feeling
that her future
will be a bright one.
The intellect of Ira Graves
has been deposited
into our computer.
There is knowledge,
but no consciousness.
The human equation
has been lost.
And you don't
remember anything?
Not a thing.
To know him is to love him
is to know him?
Perhaps it is best
that I do not remember.
I trust I did
nothing unbecoming
to a Starfleet officer?
Does wrestling with
a Klingon targ ring a bell?
Mr. Crusher, take us
out of orbit.
Aye, sir.
Did I win?