Captain's Log,
Stardate 42494.8.
The Enterprise is bound
for Star Station India
to rendezvous with
a Starfleet medical courier.
We've been told only that
our presence is imperative.
Hopefully, the mission will
give me further opportunities
to assess the performance of
our new Chief Medical Officer.
( door chime )
Come.
You wanted to see me, Captain?
Yes, Counselor.
Come.
Sit down.
Counselor,
you've had the opportunity
to observe Dr. Pulaski
for some time now.
How would you evaluate her
as a Chief Medical Officer?
I've never met
a more dedicated physician.
I would say she has
a passion for her work.
Mm, yes, of course.
I entirely agree.
Is it possible
that such consuming dedication
could interfere
with her judgment?
I feel your concern, Captain,
but I don't share it.
Perhaps because I've
had the opportunity
to spend more time
with her and get
to know her better.
Yes, perhaps you're right.
DATA:
Captain, we are picking up
a faint distress signal
on an open subspace frequency.
It appears to be coming
from an adjacent sector.
Respond on the same frequency.
Have you locked on
to that transmission?
Aye, sir.
A voice-only transmission
from the USS Lantree
a Federation
supply ship.
USS Lantree, this is Picard
of the Enterprise.
What is the nature
of your emergency?
MAN:
...can't hold out anymore.
We are dying...
Too many to help...
We are still receiving
their signal, Captain,
but there is no message.
Lantree...
are you under attack?
( static )
Lantree?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
USS Lantree,
this is the Enterprise.
Come in, Lantree.
Replay that last transmission.
...can't hold out anymore.
We are dying...
Too many to help...
Have we got
a fix on her?
2.2 milliparsecs, bearing 3-0
at 145 degrees, sir.
Number One?
We better take a look.
What kind of vessel is she?
The Lantree is a class 6
Federation supply ship
assigned to the Gamma 7 Sector.
Captain L.I. Telaka, commanding.
Normal complement,
26 officers and crew.
Armed?
Class 3, defensive only.
Is she still underway?
Aye, sir.
Adjust course to intercept.
Warp 7.
Adjusting course
to intercept.
Warp 7, sir.
Engineering, transfer to Bridge.
We are closing
on the Lantree, Captain.
Take us out of warp.
Establish parallel course
and match speed.
Yes, sir.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
Lantree, this is
the Enterprise.
Captain Telaka, this is
Picard of the Enterprise.
Do you read me?
No life signs, Captain.
Counselor?
Nothing, Captain.
RIKER:
What else have we got
in the neighborhood?
WESLEY:
No other vessels of any kind
within two parsecs.
No battle damage.
All systems seem functional,
Captain.
Everything is in
perfect order.
We have to board her, Captain.
Possibly, Mr. Worf.
Number One?
If we gain control
of her systems remotely,
we could activate
the viewscreen.
That way, at least we could
look at the Bridge.
Agreed.
Computer,
security override request.
Identify.
Picard, Jean-Luc, Captain,
USS Enterprise.
Request control access
Starfleet ship USS Lantree.
Iso Telaka, commanding.
Enter access code.
Omicron omicron alpha yellow
daystar two seven.
Enable.
DATA:
I have verified receipt
of the access codes
for the Lantree, Captain.
Grand.
Commence operations.
Our first move will be
to shut down the engines.
LA FORGE:
Standing by, Commander.
The Lantree computer
reports access codes
received and accepted, sir.
Sick Bay on alert, Captain.
The interlock is engaged.
The Lantree is responding, sir.
We have override control
of her Bridge, Captain.
All systems answering.
All right.
Let's have a look.
LA FORGE:
Lantree Bridge
monitor, engaging.
You reading
anything, Doctor?
Still no signs of life, Captain.
Magnify.
That must be Captain Telaka
on the left.
Let's look at him.
Closer.
My God.
Looks like they had
a battle with time.
And lost.
Heart, lungs, liver...
everything.
What is it?
They died of natural causes.
Natural causes?
What in nature could cause that?
PULASKI:
For the record, Captain
they died of old age.
We've downloaded
the Lantree's logs, sir.
Play back the Captain's
last entry.
Captain's Log, Stardate 42493.1.
There are only six of us left.
We've set course for
the nearest Federation outpost,
but I am afraid it's too late.
All attempts to analyze
what is happening have failed.
In the last few hours,
I've watched friends
grow old and die.
And I'm seeing it happen to me.
Captain L.I. Telaka,
USS Lantree.
Captain Telaka was my age, sir.
Doctor?
Every member of the Lantree crew
had a complete examination
at the beginning of his
duty cycle, eight weeks ago.
They were in perfect health.
Nothing else since?
A single medical entry
noting that the First Officer
was treated for Thelusian flu
five days ago.
Thelusian flu?
It's an exotic,
but harmless rhinal virus.
It couldn't have caused this.
The last port of call
for the Lantree
was the Darwin
Genetic Research Station
on Gagarin IV, three days ago.
Whatever happened,
it could be something
that the Lantree crew
already had
or it could have
come from Gagarin.
At the very least
the people from
Darwin Station
deserve a warning.
We may have to consider
a quarantine.
You'll agree that we should
quarantine the Lantree?
Absolutely.
Lieutenant, initiate
the quarantine transmitters
on the Lantree, and activate her
marker beacons.
We'll need to
find her again.
Aye, sir.
Quarantine warnings active
on all frequencies, Captain.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Extreme caution.
The USS Lantree
is a quarantined vessel
by order of Starfleet Command.
Do not board.
Set course
for Gagarin IV.
Warp 7.
Course and speed set, sir.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Extreme caution...
Engage.
...is a quarantined vessel...
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We're en route to the
Federation Research Station
on Gagarin IV.
The mere thought
of a possible connection
between the Lantree tragedy
and a genetic research facility
fills me
with profound apprehension.
We're approaching
Gagarin IV, Captain.
Standard orbit, Mr. Crusher.
Aye, sir.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
Darwin Station,
this is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
Enterprise,
this is Darwin Station.
I'm Dr. Kingsley.
We've just declared
a medical emergency here.
We need your help.
Uh, Dr. Kingsley,
what is the nature
of your emergency?
To whom am I speaking, please?
I'm Dr. Pulaski,
Chief Medical Officer.
Katherine Pulaski?
Author of Linear Models
of Viral Propagation?
That was a long time ago.
But still the standard.
I can't think of anyone
I'd rather be dealing with.
Doctor, we're experiencing
the rapid onset
of geriatric phenomena.
The first symptom is sudden,
acute arthritic inflammation.
Then the aging process
accelerates.
The Lantree.
Dr. Pulaski,
I celebrated my 35th
birthday a week ago.
Doctor, we understand
that Darwin Station
is involved in genetic research.
Is there a possible connection?
Our research here is
limited to human genetics.
I can assure you
we're not dealing
with something
that got away from us.
We believe that we were infected
by a supply ship
that was here three days ago.
Doctor, if you're speaking
of the Lantree,
we encountered it
a few hours ago.
All the crew members were dead.
Which would seem
to confirm our suspicion.
Were you able to establish
a pathology, Doctor?
Doctor, did you hear
what I said?
All the 26 men and women
aboard that ship were dead.
I heard you, Captain,
and the prognosis is alarming,
but my immediate concern
is our children.
Children?
They represent years
of advanced genetic research.
You must evacuate them
as soon as possible.
I'm sorry,
but under the circumstances
until we know what's going on,
I'm imposing a full quarantine
on Darwin Station.
But the children have been
in protective isolation
since this was detected.
They've shown no symptoms.
You cannot leave them
here to die.
Doctor, our options
in a quarantine situation
are extremely limited.
We are going to consider
the possibilities.
I suggest you do the same.
I recommend against
contact, Captain.
Number One?
I have to agree, sir.
I wish there was something
we could do,
but I think the risk
is too great.
Doctor?
If the children are
free of disease
as Dr. Kingsley said,
they should be evacuated.
I would like to bring
one of them aboard
within a forcefield,
for a complete examination.
Counselor?
Do you sense
anything?
Dr. Kingsley sincerely believes
the children are not a threat,
but she's not telling us
the whole truth.
I recommend caution.
We have only
Dr. Kingsley's assurance
that these children
are not infected
whereas, we have seen
the results of this disease
firsthand.
In a case like this,
I think we should err
on the side of caution.
All right.
We could beam up one child
encased in styrolite
in suspended animation.
That way, I could scan
for possible infection
without danger to ourselves
or to the child.
But we don't know
what we're looking for.
Exactly.
And we won't
until we start gathering data.
Captain, that's
worth some risk.
There's always risk, Doctor.
( sighs )
Proceed with the examination.
But I shall require
positive proof
that these children are harmless
before I place any of my crew
in jeopardy.
Forcefield is ready, Captain.
Activate.
Transporter?
This is Chief O'Brien, sir.
Almost ready.
Is there a problem?
It's the styrolite.
I'm altering the delta-t
so the styrolite coating
materializes
two microseconds
ahead of the child.
It has to be right
the first time.
Well, take all
the time you need.
Entering corrections now, sir.
Ready, Captain.
Dr. Kingsley, are you
ready to transport?
KINGSLEY:
You have the coordinates.
We have one 12-year-old male
encased in number six styrolite.
Transporter...
energize.
A trick!
Transporter reverse...
One moment, Lieutenant.
Whoever he is,
he's still in stasis.
Styrolite is intact, Captain.
Forcefield down.
Captain,
there's a definite
presence.
A distinct
personality.
Even in stasis,
it's quite strong.
The child is
unquestionably
telepathic.
PULASKI:
A child
this mature?
We could be looking
at the future of humanity.
Hmm.
At least Dr. Kingsley's
vision of it.
This child is in better
health than we are.
His immune system
is so advanced,
it may not be possible
for him to contract disease.
I want to free him
from the styrolite.
That seems rather
risky, Doctor.
I can do no further tests
until he's animate.
But what if you're wrong?
You saw what happened
on the Lantree.
I know I'm right.
I can't expose
the Enterprise
until I know
where this disease came from
and how it is transmitted.
I realize that, Captain.
Naturally, we'll establish
a forcefield containment.
But if we lose the forcefield
for any reason,
we lose the ship.
Forcefields can fail,
and until...
We don't have that kind of time.
These children can't survive
in the lab
once their parents are dead.
Look at him,
Captain.
He's a human being
who needs our help.
But the risk is...
Minimal.
If you can
demonstrate
that he is biologically harmless
without risk to the crew,
I'll do everything in my power
to assist.
And, Doctor, God knows
I'm not one to discourage input,
but I would appreciate it
if you'd let me finish
my sentences
once in awhile.
Deanna.
Do you have a minute?
Mm-hmm.
You've known
the Captain
for some time.
I think I need
some advice.
I don't seem to
be dealing with
him very well.
Why do you say that?
Well, my arguments
don't seem to have
any effect on him.
We just end up quoting
regulations to each other.
He has such a consuming
dedication to his ship.
He doesn't seem to
be able to step back
to see the human side
of the equation.
What's the matter?
Kate, I don't think
he'd be where he is
if he couldn't see
the human side of the equation.
Perhaps the two of you
aren't all that different.
What do you mean?
Let's just say,
you both have
well-established
personalities.
Dr. Kingsley,
this is Kate Pulaski.
Doctor, do you have a decision?
I'm afraid it's bad news.
How can that be?
The risk to the ship and crew
is too great.
Until we absolutely know
the cause of the disease
the children...
The children are harmless.
Every test on them
has been negative.
I demand that you do something
to save them.
Please, Doctor.
For God's sake,
we haven't got much time.
Stand by.
I'll get back to you.
Geordi, I need your help.
What is it, Doctor?
I need to prove that
the children are harmless.
I can only do that
in a fail-safe environment.
The problem is,
there's no area of the ship
that can be sealed off
with absolute certainty.
Even with forcefields...
Sick Bay has
an isolated system.
But it's not possible
to totally cut it off
from the rest of the ship.
The only truly
independent environment
would be
something like...
like a shuttlecraft.
A shuttlecraft.
Why didn't you say so?
( door chime )
Come.
Captain, I'd like permission to
put the boy in a shuttlecraft.
I can study him there
without risk to anyone else.
What about you?
I'm prepared to take that risk.
Someone has to breathe
the same air he breathes.
To touch him.
I'm volunteering to make
that test myself.
Doctor, you have
a responsibility
to this ship, which goes...
I also have a responsibility
to humanity.
Starfleet guidelines
about contact with
quarantined vess...
You don't have to quote
the rule book.
You were saying?
Request approved.
Captain, you said if I...
Approved?
I recognize that you're trying
to satisfy my conditions.
Thank you.
You sent for me, Doctor?
I did, Commander.
I assume that
you're qualified
to pilot this
shuttlecraft?
DATA:
Certainly.
I took advanced training
in the operation
of auxiliary space vessels
at Starfleet academy
where I received...
A more than passing
grade, no doubt.
Please, come aboard.
We don't have
much time.
( alarm beeping )
COMPUTER:
Shuttle Bay Three
forcefield activated.
You are certain the Captain
approved this, Doctor?
You'll take us
a few hundred meters
away from the Enterprise
and hold position.
Begin shuttlecraft
launch sequence.
Good luck, Doctor.
We are in position,
Doctor.
It's the only way to prove
they're harmless.
And if they are not?
I hate to keep reminding you,
but you are a machine.
You'll be perfectly safe.
That is by no means certain,
Doctor,
but I was referring to you.
Medical research is sometimes
a risky business.
It's all part of being human.
Shall we proceed?
Ready to transport.
DATA:
You have the coordinates,
Chief O'Brien.
Shuttlecraft, maintain
your position and stand by.
Standing by.
Transporter Control,
what's our status?
We have a green panel, sir.
Stand by to transport.
Aye, sir.
Energize.
Oh, yes.
I do.
I understand you perfectly.
How could you, Doctor?
He has not said anything.
Oh, yes, he has.
Troi is right.
He's telepathic.
Time?
COMPUTER:
0322, exactly.
She's been in direct contact
with the boy for 18 minutes.
All systems are functioning
within normal specifications,
Doctor.
The manufacturer will
be pleased to hear it.
I appreciate your help,
but your bedside
manner needs work.
Bedside manner?
( gasping )
Doctor?
PICARD:
Doctor, I don't understand.
What has happened?
There was no warning.
Explain.
Arthritic inflammation.
It's the initial symptom
of the disease.
What can we do?
Return the boy
to Darwin Station.
Apparently,
the children are carriers.
PICARD:
Chief O'Brien, are you ready?
I have the original coordinates
of the Darwin isolation lab,
Captain.
Quickly, please.
Shuttle one, hold your position.
Holding.
O'BRIEN:
Stand by to transport.
It wasn't your fault.
PICARD:
Tell us what you need, Doctor.
There's nothing you can do,
Captain.
I'm not going to make myself
an exception
to the Darwin quarantine.
Shuttle One, out.
What is your
condition, Doctor?
Not exactly
up to factory specs.
I'm sorry.
The pain is tolerable.
Thank you.
Shall I set course
for Darwin Station?
We're already
under quarantine.
What do we have to lose?
We can no longer consider
the Darwin Station crisis
our most immediate concern.
Although Dr. Pulaski's condition
is inseparably linked
with that emergency,
her safe return
and that of Commander Data
must take priority, please.
Shouldn't Dr. Pulaski
be involved in this?
From what we've seen
on the Lantree,
Dr. Pulaski may not have time
to help herself.
Well, I suggest
we beam them both
back onto the ship.
Commander Data is
most likely immune
and surely the bio-filter...
Oh, the transporter's
bio-filter won't protect us.
The boy was transported
twice already
and still infected
Dr. Pulaski.
Yeah, but couldn't we adjust
the bio-filter?
We can alter the filter
to screen out
whatever it is
that's causing the disease.
But we don't know what's causing
the disease.
We can't protect ourselves
against the unknown.
What we need is
some kind of filter
that doesn't depend
on known biological factors.
We might try the trace.
The transporter trace?
Well, as you know,
the transporter
keeps a record
of all transmissions--
a pattern, if you will.
Usually, it's just stored
for security purposes,
but if we use
the transporter trace
to control
the reconstitution process...
I don't think it's ever been
tried quite that way before,
but, theoretically,
it is possible.
I'd have to make
extensive modifications.
Then do it.
Seems we have no alternative.
Where will we get
the trace pattern?
The Doctor's never used
our transporter.
Never?
No, she's a woman of very
strongly held opinions, sir.
What was her
previous assignment?
Her last ship
was the Repulse.
Bridge, Picard.
Contact the USS Repulse
using subspace
Captain's priority channel.
Oh, Dr. Pulaski...
I can only tell you
how much I regret
the burden
we've imposed on you.
On both of you.
Commander Data
is an android.
He's unaffected.
As for me,
I chose this.
I was convinced
the children were safe.
I still can't believe you were
infected by one of our children.
The evidence is
fairly conclusive.
You don't understand.
They were designed
to resist disease.
I think it's time
we talked about that.
Let me show you something.
Our ultimate achievement.
The oldest is 12
and all are telekinetic.
Watch.
Genetically engineered?
Not engineered, created.
Perfect in every way--
their body structure,
their musculature, their minds.
You were telling me
about their
immune system.
That was our masterpiece.
We gave these children
an aggressive immunity.
The rest of us were infected
by the supply ship,
but they were protected.
The Lantree logs indicated
that only one crewman
had any illness
prior to arrival here.
The First Officer had
a mild case of Thelusian flu.
Yes, he was one of the crewmen
who came
in direct contact with us.
The Thelusian flu would have
little effect on you,
but, tell me,
how would they react?
Their immune system would
release an active antibody
that would attack the virus.
Even at a distance?
Their immune systems don't wait
for a disease
to attack the body.
It would seek out an airborne
virus and destroy it.
Destroy it?
How exactly?
The antibody would adapt itself
to alter the genetic code
of the virus.
Commander, I want
an analysis of
the interaction
between the Thelusian
flu and the children.
On a molecular
genetic level?
We don't have
time for that.
Genetic analysis
could take months.
Not necessarily.
Commander Data has
a way with computers.
Sorry, Picard.
We erased Dr. Pulaski's
transporter pattern
right after she transferred.
Not that she used
the transporter much.
She preferred the shuttlecraft.
I would have given her a shuttle
if it would have kept her here.
Tell me, Taggert, if she served
you as well as you say,
why did you let her go?
I see you haven't run
into her stubborn streak yet.
As soon as she found out about
an opening on the Enterprise,
she put in a request
for transfer.
Knew your service record
backward and forward.
Apparently, she's been an
admirer of yours for some time.
Extraordinary.
Commander...
what have you got?
The answer,
I believe, Doctor.
The Lantree was not
the source of the disease,
but it was the trigger.
Trigger?
The Lantree's First Officer
exposed your children
to Thelusian flu
for the first time.
Their active immune systems
set out to attack the virus
and once it was triggered,
it kept going.
But the antibody created
an unexpected side effect.
It alters the genetic makeup
of normal humans.
This is a comparison
of the altered and normal DNA.
These are the two molecules
that have been transposed.
And since our DNA
is self-replicating,
the process...
Is irreversible.
Judging from what happened
on the Lantree,
anyone is a carrier
once they're infected.
Oh.
Have you made
any progress, Doctor?
I'm afraid so, Captain.
The children don't
carry the disease.
They are the cause.
What do you mean?
Their advanced immune system
has created an antibody
that changes normal DNA.
The altered genes are the ones
that control aging.
Then why did it attack
you more quickly
than Dr. Kingsley?
The enclosed environment
of the shuttlecraft
concentrated my exposure.
The Lantree's First Officer
carried the antibody
onto his ship.
It had the same effect
on his crew.
Right, what's the next step?
The children will survive,
but the rest of us
are just about out of time.
Doctor, I want you
back aboard this ship.
We'll beam you up in
suspended animation
like the boy.
That will give us more time.
Captain, I appreciate
what you're trying to do,
but I got into this
by leaping before I looked
and I won't allow you
to make the same mistake.
Chief Medical Officer's log.
This will be my final report
to the Enterprise.
Just as changes in evolution
are known to be caused
by changes in the environment,
we now know the process
also works in reverse.
An attempt
to control human evolution
has resulted in a new species
that's lethal
to its predecessors.
The children will be condemned
to live out their lives
in isolation.
The quarantine
of the Darwin Station
must be maintained forever.
I am sorry I could
not be more helpful, Doctor.
You did everything
you could, Commander.
As androids go, you're
in a class by yourself.
Doctor...
Please.
Give my best to the Captain.
Enterprise, Commander Data
ready to beam aboard.
Captain,
Kate knew what she was doing.
I wish I could be certain
that we'd tried everything.
Commander Data is ready
to come aboard, sir.
You have the Bridge, Number One.
No life-forms present, sir.
You may
step down, sir.
Data, tell me, if...
It's good to see you again.
Thank you, sir.
Now, quickly-- if the changes in
Dr. Pulaski's DNA were reversed,
would it be possible...
It is not reversible, sir.
The subtle molecular
transposition...
Yes, yes, yes,
but say if it were "undone,"
would she be normal again?
As normal as ever, sir.
You said that the transporter
could be modified
to filter out the changes
in Dr. Pulaski.
Yes, sir, but we were unable
to locate her trace pattern.
Well...
what if we used
a sample of her DNA--
say, um, from a blood test--
taken before she was exposed
to the disease--
could that be used to filter out
the genetic changes?
Well, I'd have to get
into the bio-filter bus
and patch in a molecular
matrix reader.
That's no problem.
But the waveform modulator
will be overloaded
without the regeneration
limiter
in the first stage circuit.
Hmm, interesting.
However,
theoretically...
Data.
Yes, sir.
Can you do the modifications?
I think so, sir.
Then make it so.
You heard what he said.
Let's get those panels off.
A blood test, a tissue sample--
anything that would have
a sample of Dr. Pulaski's
original DNA.
No, sir, her records
were shipped
by way of Starfleet
Headquarters.
They have not
caught up with us yet.
This is ridiculous.
A cell, a single cell...
Let's check her quarters.
Anything--
a fingernail, a hair...
Hairbrush.
It has a follicle, sir.
Live cells.
Darwin Station,
this is the Enterprise.
PULASKI:
Go ahead, Captain.
I'm here.
PICARD:
Doctor, we may have a solution.
We have a sample
of your normal DNA
to use as a filter
in the transporter.
We think
that we can beam you aboard
while filtering out
any of the genetic problems
caused by the disease.
Interesting theory, Captain.
If it works, we could use
the same technique
to save Dr. Kingsley
and her colleagues.
I think you should know this
has never been attempted before.
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
If I live through this...
I'll have a much better
understanding of geriatrics.
All set, Chief?
Almost ready, sir.
There's just one thing.
Yes?
This modification's
one way only.
If it doesn't work,
we won't be able
to reverse-transport
the Doctor back
to the planet.
Then, I'll operate the
transporter controls myself.
If she's going to be consigned
to oblivion, then...
Thank you, sir.
I'll be monitoring
the medical scans,
but you'll be able
to tell if it's worked
by watching the stack.
Dr. Pulaski, are you ready?
I suppose I am, Captain.
Here we go.
PICARD:
It's not working.
O'BRIEN:
Captain, wait.
( beeping )
Doctor.
Good to see you, Doctor.
Welcome back, Doctor.
Come.
Captain, if this
hadn't worked...
if...
If this hadn't worked,
it would have
been necessary
to beam your energy
into empty space.
And spread my atoms
across the galaxy.
Yes, I'm sorry...
No, no, don't be sorry.
Every time I get
into the damned thing,
I'm convinced that's
what's going to happen.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental.
The adults of Darwin station
have been restored
to normal health
using our transporter.
They will remain on Gagarin IV
and continue their research
in hopes of one day
rejoining their children.
Impulse speed.
There she is,
Captain.
Scientists believe
no experiment is a failure,
that even a mistake advances
the evolution of understanding.
Close to 40 kilometers.
40 kilometers.
Aye, sir.
But all achievement
has a price.
For one brief glimpse
at the mysterious blueprint
of human evolution,
the men and women
of the USS Lantree
paid with their lives.
Their sacrifice is thus noted
in this scientist's log.
Number One.
Lieutenant Worf,
arm the photon torpedoes.
Torpedoes ready, Commander.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Extreme caution.
The USS Lantree is
a quarantined vessel
by order of Starfleet Command.
Do not board.
Gentlemen.
Extreme caution.
The USS Lantree is
a quarantined vessel
by order of Starfleet Command.
Do not board.
Set course and speed
for Star Station India.
WESLEY:
Course and speed set, sir.
Engage.