We are approaching
Starbase 179, sir.
Half impulse, Mr. Crusher.
Going to half impulse.
Captain, this is the Bridge.
We've arrived at Starbase 179.
PICARD:
Acknowledged, Number One.
Establish position
090-mark-345
at 27,000
kilometers.
Hailing
frequencies.
Open.
Starbase 179,
this is the Enterprise.
Enterprise,
this is Starbase 179.
We are ready for transfer
on your mark.
Thank you.
Commander Data,
you have the Bridge.
Ensign Crusher,
you're with me.
Starbase 179, we are ready
to commence transfer.
Acknowledge, Enterprise.
Begin transfer.
Welcome aboard
the Enterprise.
I'm Commander William Riker,
your First Officer.
Those of you who are here
as replacements
can step outside
and follow Lieutenant Lewis.
He will assign you
to your crew quarters.
Ensign, you are here
on the exchange program.
If you would just
follow Mr. Crusher.
Mordock, what are
you doing here?
You couldn't
have graduated
the academy already.
I am not Mordock.
I am Mendon.
Ensign Mendon from
the planet Benzar.
Sorry.
It's a friend of mine.
You look
just like him.
We are from the same
geostructure.
Naturally, we look alike.
How do you tell
each other apart?
We just do.
It's nice to have you here,
Ensign.
There will be
a briefing
and indoctrination session
in 15 minutes.
I want to tell you
how happy I am
to be assigned
to the Enterprise.
It wasn't just luck.
I requested it.
I know I can be of great help
to the ship.
Yes, of course.
If you'll just
follow Mr. Crusher.
Yes, sir.
( chuckling )
PICARD:
Commander Riker,
report to the phaser range,
please.
On my way.
( targets beeping,
shots whooshing )
PICARD:
I was wondering if
you had any feelings
about the officer
exchange program
initiated by
Starfleet Command.
Just positive ones, sir.
Actually, I just welcomed
Ensign Mendon onboard.
He certainly seems
eager to please.
Well, that's
a Benzite trait.
It's been suggested
that an officer
from the Enterprise
might participate
in the program.
That's probably a good idea.
Well, there is
a Klingon vessel
in the area.
I don't recall hearing
of a Federation officer
ever serving
on a Klingon vessel.
No, no, neither have I.
It might prove
to be beneficial.
Well, having Worf onboard
certainly has been.
Yes, sir.
Who did you intend to send, sir?
I thought of asking
for a volunteer.
I might be interested, sir.
Damn.
Sorry, Number One,
what was that?
I said I wouldn't mind
the assignment, sir.
Any particular reason?
Because nobody has ever
done it before.
Well, I'll inform Starbase
of your acceptance.
They'll contact
the Klingon vessel,
make the arrangements.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42506.5.
We have departed
from Starbase 179
and are headed for a rendezvous
with the Klingon vessel Pagh.
I have informed the staff
of Commander Riker's
temporary assignment.
I've studied, and know
everything about my heritage.
Then you're just the person
I need to talk to
to clear something up.
It's been my understanding
that one of the duties
of the First Officer
of the Klingon vessel
is to assassinate
his Captain?
Yes, sir.
Wouldn't that
bring about chaos?
Of course not.
See, when and if the
Captain becomes weak
or unable to perform,
it is expected that
his honorable retirement
should be assisted
by his "First."
Your Second Officer
will assassinate you
for the same reasons.
That method of attrition must
take a little getting used to.
The Klingon system has
operated successfully
for centuries.
It is different.
Many things will
be different.
Can I help you, sir?
That's a wonderful method
of maintaining
a constant control factor
over defensive shields,
but I'm sure there's a way
to improve
response time.
Sorry.
Didn't mean to interrupt you.
Just thought
I could be of some help.
However, I am correct
in what I said.
That is superb designing,
absolutely first-rate.
Yes, it is.
Would you care to be
more specific?
The input sampling.
It's simple, yet
efficient enough.
Of course, a minor change
of the helm readout
would be much
more helpful
in emergency
situations.
We've never had
any problems with it.
Have you seen it work?
Not in a practical exercise,
but in theory.
My theory-- it would be more
than a marginal improvement.
I'll have
to mention this
to the Captain.
He is open to some astute
observations, isn't he?
I've never known the Captain
not to listen
to one of his officers.
Outstanding.
Soon, we'll get things
running perfectly.
What is that?
It's a Klingon delicacy.
Pipius claw.
This is heart of targ.
This, of course, is gagh.
Gagh?
Yes, serpent worms.
Would you like some?
No, thanks.
I've never heard of a Klingon
starving to death
on his own vessel,
but you might.
Not if I weaken first.
I know all about that.
Their beliefs
are rather brutal,
but usually what kills us
kills them.
Well, that's certainly
good to know.
Would you like
something to drink?
I'm abstaining in honor
of your last hour onboard.
Your sacrifice
will not go unnoticed.
Oh.
Well, I'm familiar
with the practice
of the feast
before the transfer.
I've done it
dozens of times.
However, I usually made
more palatable choices.
Well, these are
the more palatable choices.
Ah, thank you.
Hmm.
We know so little about them.
There really is
so much to learn.
This is a great opportunity.
I envy you, Mr. Riker.
Oh!
Well.
Yeah, thank you.
Oh...
( crunching )
Mmm.
Commander.
An emergency
transponder?
Slightly altered to transmit
an omnidirectional signal
and an emergency call.
You suspect
trouble?
Simply a security
precaution.
I want to ensure your return
to this ship.
Sentiment,
Lieutenant Worf?
Efficiency, Commander.
I understand.
Thank you.
( beeping )
We have a Klingon
vessel approaching.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
They are returning
our hail
in proper language.
It is the Pagh.
On viewscreen.
I'm Captain Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
This is Captain Kargan
of the Klingon vessel, the Pagh.
Beam your First Officer
onboard immediately.
We are preparing to do so.
And, Captain, you're getting
a fine officer.
Thank you for your opinion,
but I will judge that
for myself.
Screen off.
Not very hospitable,
are they?
That is not
your concern.
Observe your station,
Ensign Mendon.
Didn't mean to offend you.
You didn't.
Yet.
( screen beeping rhythmically)
Transporter,
prepare to beam
Commander Riker
aboard the Pagh.
Acknowledged, Captain.
Mr. Data, you
have the Bridge.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
Good luck,
Commander.
Thanks, O'Brien.
I wouldn't
want to go.
Why?
You're not afraid, are you?
No, I'm not.
I would be.
Ready, sir.
Thanks.
Energize.
PICARD:
Resume course, Mr. Crusher.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Take over, Commander Data.
I'll be in Observation.
Thank you, sir.
Sir, I am
Ensign Mendon.
I just wanted
to tell you
how pleased I am to be
aboard the Enterprise.
Yes, of course.
Um...
good to have you aboard.
If you have a few minutes,
I've noted a few
procedural changes
which might speed up
operations on the Bridge.
I pick things up
very fast.
Yes, of course you do.
Your have an excellent record,
Ensign.
However, here on the Enterprise,
we use the chain of command.
You will report
your observations
to Lieutenant Worf.
I beg your pardon,
Captain.
I just wanted
to impress upon you...
No need to apologize, Ensign.
We should have explained
it better to you
at your indoctrination.
Ensign Mendon...
you may impress me.
( indistinct conversations
in Klingon )
Something wrong?
No.
It's just...
I've never seen anyone
of your species before.
I'm just your average,
everyday human being
who happens
to be a Commander.
Now what were
your orders?
To escort you
to the Captain.
Proceed.
Yes, Commander.
Commander William
Riker of the Starship
Enterprise.
That is incorrect.
I don't
understand.
You are Commander William Riker,
First Officer
of the Klingon Cruiser the Pagh.
Or do you intend to disobey
Federation orders?
I have no such intentions, sir.
Exactly where are
your loyalties, Commander?
I'm afraid I still
don't understand, sir.
This ship is equipped
with our best weapons
and our finest warriors.
Although we're
on a peaceful mission,
we are ready to go
into battle instantly.
I know I can count on every
Klingon warrior in this crew
to serve and die
in that battle.
So I ask you again,
Commander Riker,
where are your loyalties?
I've been assigned
to serve this ship
and to obey
your orders.
And I will do exactly that.
Will you take an oath
to that effect?
I just did.
This is your Second Officer,
Lieutenant Klag.
Was there
something
you wanted to say to me,
Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
I do not believe you.
Then I take it you challenge
my authority over you.
Correct.
And your position on this,
Captain?
I would say it is
your first command decision.
( growls softly )
My oath is between
Captain Kargan and myself.
Your only concern
is with how you obey my orders.
Or do you prefer
the rank of prisoner
to that
of Lieutenant?
I will take your orders.
And you, Commander Riker,
obey my orders.
Of course,
Captain Kargan.
Sir, automatic scan has
registered an unknown substance
on the aft quarter
of the exterior skin
of the dorsal section.
Target that location
and define.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
I've located it, sir.
The dorsal
of the Engineering section.
Viewscreen on.
Focus on area.
Magnification
factor ten.
Increase magnification
to 50.
PICARD:
Analyze.
The substance
appears to be
a rare form
of subatomic bacteria
capable of doubling itself
in size every 15 minutes.
It seems to be reacting with
two of the compounds present
in the Enterprise structure.
Origin?
MENDON:
Captain,
I noticed it when I did an
intensive scan of the Pagh.
The Klingon ship.
And whom did you inform?
Well, no one.
I have not yet completed
my full analysis.
You are supposed to report
whatever is out of the ordinary.
And I think that falls
into this category.
But, sir, as I said,
I've not yet completed
my full analysis.
It would be improper
to report it until then.
How did you come
to that decision?
It is a Benzite regulation.
No officer on the deck
of one of our ships
would report an occurrence
like this
until he had a full analysis
and a resolution.
I have simply followed
proper procedures.
It is our procedure, Ensign,
to notify Command
of any possible danger
to the ship.
The decision is not yours.
Do you
understand?
Yes, sir.
Now, you will continue
with your analysis
and determine the danger
not only to our ship
but to the Klingon vessel, also.
Yes, Captain.
That will take
a couple of hours.
Use whatever resources
are necessary.
It appears we may have
encountered a new life-form.
I want to know everything
about it as quickly as possible.
Commander Data,
supervise.
Aye, sir.
And then I will instruct you
in Enterprise etiquette.
First Officer's Personal Log.
I have been aboard the Pagh
a short time
but long enough to be
impressed with the abilities
and single-mindedness
of the Klingons.
( speaking Klingon )
Commander,
you're not eating very much.
I'm not that hungry.
Is the food
all right, Commander?
It's delicious.
The pipius claw was excellent.
I also enjoyed this bregitlung.
And the rokeg blood pie?
Delicious.
Good.
Then you'll also enjoy this.
Isn't that gagh?
Very good.
You did some research
on our nutritional choices.
Yes, but...
it's still moving.
Gagh is always best
when served live.
Would you like something easier?
Easier?
Yes.
If Klingon food
is too strong for you,
perhaps we could get
one of the females
to breast-feed you.
( laughter )
You're not worried
about my weakening, are you?
Look around you.
There are no old warriors.
No, sir, I'm sure
they all died with honor.
Exactly.
You may live long enough
to learn about us.
He is not very
attractive,
but I will have him.
They are inquisitive.
They would like to know
how you would endure.
Endure what?
Them.
One or both?
( laughter )
I may be back for you.
Is she serious?
Yes.
Commander, would you say
you're a typical
Federation officer?
I suppose so.
Why?
Well, it's just
you're not what I expected.
In what way?
You have a sense of humor.
I was thinking
the same thing about you.
In all my dealings
with Klingons,
including our
Lieutenant Worf,
the thought
never occurred to me
of Klingons laughing.
There is much about us
you do not know.
That's why I'm here.
You should ask.
I may.
After this tour,
I may have
some worthy questions.
Questions about what?
About our future?
Our future is honor.
Our present is
serving this ship.
Like you, I have
a mother
and a father.
They look like me.
I look like them.
Are they still alive?
My mother lives and my father
was killed in battle
at Tranome Sar.
And your father?
My father?
My father was captured
in battle by Romulans
and not allowed to die.
He eventually escaped.
Where is he now?
He is on our planet.
He waits.
He waits for his death.
He will eventually fade
of a natural illness
and die weakened and useless.
Honorless.
I will not see him.
He's your father.
A Klingon is his work,
not his family.
That is the way of things.
He's your father.
Klingons do not express feeling
the way you do.
Perhaps you should.
We would not know how.
Yesterday, I did not
know how to eat gagh.
MENDON:
It is confirmed
that the organisms feed
on some of the compounds
that make up the hull
of the Enterprise.
And the Klingon ship, the Pagh?
They are more susceptible.
Their hull contains more
of the compounds.
Projection.
According to the rate
of reproduction,
there should be a
12-centimeter opening
in the Klingon hull
at this time.
Signal them at once.
They could be unaware
of their danger.
They may need our help.
Aye, sir.
Change course to intercept.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
It will take some time
to locate them, sir.
They are on
undesignated maneuvers
in the Pheben
system.
Find them.
Tell me, Commander Riker.
What do you make of this?
RIKER:
I felt no collision.
Were we hit
by a small meteor?
No. No collision.
Corrosion, then?
No, not corrosion.
Science station,
analyze.
We already have
and fortunately
the cavity opened
onto a section
that could withstand
the change in pressure.
Then, what is it?
KLAG:
A space organism
eating away at our hull.
What are you talking about?
What is it?
I mean, you must have
some way to repair it.
I'm afraid not.
KLAG:
Our estimate
is that, in less than eight
hours, we will have lost
too much of our shell
to remain intact.
The only vessel
we've had contact with recently
is the Enterprise.
There was no direct contact
with the Enterprise.
Tactics officer,
report to Commander Riker.
The Enterprise did conduct
an extensive scan
of this vessel.
That's normal procedure.
What type of beam
did the Enterprise use
to cause this damage
to our hull?
None.
Why would they do that?
We're allies.
But my logs indicate
that the Enterprise directed
an intense
scanning beam
at this specific area
for a duration of two minutes.
Explain that.
I can't.
It could be a weapon.
It's no weapon.
The Enterprise
has no reason to do that,
especially with me onboard.
It makes no sense.
Why?
"Why" is no longer important.
What is important
is our response to this attack.
Engage cloaking device.
Change course
to intercept the Enterprise.
What do you intend to do,
Captain?
Intend?
There is only one response.
I intend to attack
the Enterprise
and destroy it.
You're making
some progress.
You've eliminated
half the possibilities already.
Thank you, but I seem
to have become efficient
a little later than was needed.
It was my responsibility
to learn and adapt
to the Enterprise's
regulations,
and I didn't do that.
Not really.
You just made an error.
Captain Picard
may not like them,
but he knows they turn up
from time to time.
I failed.
I had an opportunity
to show the Captain
my superior capabilities
and I failed.
I can never recover from that.
Mendon, it was a mistake.
You didn't put
the organism on the hull.
You discovered it.
You were trying to analyze it
and messed up
on protocol a little.
I realize you are trying
to be nice to me
and I appreciate it.
What I don't understand is why.
Why not?
I thought you
could use a friend.
Thank you.
I only hope
I can learn your ways
before I mess up again.
I imagine my methods
must seem foolish to you.
They're... different.
But that's what this exchange
program is all about.
You learn the way
we do things
and take that information
back to your command.
It's up to them to decide
which is better.
You're right.
I'll do it your way.
I'll work even harder
than I did before
and I'll succeed brilliantly.
What is the status?
Unchanged.
The rate of increase continues.
Commander Riker,
check the organism growth
with Engineering.
Keep him under scrutiny.
Captain, I'm not convinced
Riker knew
of any plot against us.
If he did, why would
he have come onboard?
Because he was ordered to.
To die?
It is the expectation
of any officer
to be ordered to
die at any time.
For a Klingon,
perhaps,
but Riker's people do not
volunteer for death so easily.
He may be a spy,
but he's no coward.
That only proves
that he's intelligent
and you might not be as strong
as you used to be.
( indignant snort )
Captain, I've picked up
the Enterprise.
So soon?
The Enterprise is
on an intercept course with us.
You almost had me believing
this was a misunderstanding.
But?
The Enterprise
has changed course
and it's following us.
Why?!
Ask them.
The reason is obvious.
Their intent is clear.
How long before we make contact?
Less than
15 minutes, sir.
Put the ship on
full battle alert.
Arm all photon
torpedoes.
Let them charge
into their destruction!
Captain, our
bearings show
that we should be
in contact with the
Klingon vessel now.
Slow to impulse.
Aye, sir, impulse speed.
Hailing frequencies are open.
There's no response.
Continue transmission.
The Pagh is either
cloaked or destroyed, sir.
Conduct an intensive scan
of the area.
The Enterprise has slowed
to impulse speed
and is making
an intensive sweep.
Hold your position.
Let them come to us.
They may be here
to help you.
Don't be a fool.
Do not forget my rank!
I haven't.
I am simply trying
to help you understand.
I understand fully.
Now, you understand.
I am still Captain
of this vessel
and you are still crew
and sworn to obey me.
You gave me your oath.
Yes, sir, I did.
Then fulfill that oath and serve
this ship as you swore to.
Tell me the surest
method of attack
against the Enterprise.
I won't.
You must.
It is a matter of honor
and loyalty to your oath.
I will not surrender
the secrets of the
Enterprise to you.
If your word is no good,
then how can we ever
trust Starfleet?
I will not break
any vow that I have
taken in the past.
I have also taken an oath
of loyalty to your ship.
I will not break that.
They are in conflict!
No, sir, they are not.
I will obey
your orders.
I will serve this ship
as First Officer.
And in an attack
against the Enterprise,
I will die with this crew.
But I will not
break my oath of
loyalty to Starfleet.
If you had told those secrets
about the Enterprise,
I would have
labeled you a traitor
and killed you where you stood.
But, instead,
you will die with us.
You will die like a Klingon.
Sir, I have something
to report to you immediately.
Yes, go ahead, Ensign.
I have managed to isolate
the organisms on our hull.
They are a sub-micron form
capable of breaking
nuclear bonds
in the tritanium plating.
But can they be removed
from the hull?
Yes.
They are controllable
and can be removed from
the hulls of both ships
by using a tunneling
neutrino beam.
Thank you, Ensign.
Well done.
Initiate
that procedure.
Lieutenant--
add that information
to the hailing messages.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant.
The Enterprise has
changed hailing messages.
They now include a promise
of cleaning the organisms
and helping in repairs.
I told you, they're
here to help.
I do not believe them.
Arm all weapons.
Prepare to attack.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42507.8.
Although our search
has been extensive,
we are still unable to locate
the Klingon ship
or any evidence
of its destruction.
Considering the absence
of debris, Captain,
it is reasonable to assume
that the Klingon vessel
is in the area and cloaked.
Agreed.
And since we do not
know its intent,
I recommend we go
to red alert.
Make it so,
Lieutenant.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
The Enterprise has
raised it's shields.
That's a normal
procedure
when entering
into a suspicious
situation.
It's not an act
of aggression.
The Enterprise
will not fire first.
Then they are fools...
for we will.
You'll get
only one shot.
We'll only need one.
Stand by on phasers
and torpedoes.
Prepare to fire them
simultaneously.
I recommend you don't fire
until you're
within 40,000 kilometers.
Why?
It will cut down
their response time.
You are honoring
your promise to serve us?
Would you do less?
You will give the order
to fire,
Commander Riker.
Call out distances.
Any questions, Mr. Riker?
There's one thing
I'd like to say.
I question your judgment.
In my opinion,
your reason for forcing
this confrontation is not valid.
Are you finished?
Yes, sir.
Commence with attack as ordered.
55,000 kilometers
and closing.
Is that a weapon,
Commander?
No, sir.
Give it to me.
We are receiving
an emergency signal
from a command
transponder.
Location
035-mark-313.
Frequency and code designate it
as Commander Riker.
Chief O'Brien, lock
onto that transponder signal.
Yes, Captain.
We're not yet in safe range
for a transfer.
And defensive shields
are still in place.
We may have
to stretch it.
We have to know what's going on
and Command Riker
is the only one
who can tell us.
We'll beam him directly
here, onto the Bridge.
On my command.
Yes, sir.
I'll wait till 40,000.
Forty-eight thousand.
Forty-four
thousand.
Transporter Room,
stand by.
You control the shields.
Ready, sir.
Forty thousand.
Forty thousand
kilometers.
Prepare to drop cloaking shields
and fire when ready.
Steady.
Transporter Room,
energize.
Hold where
you are, Klag.
I've relieved Captain Kargan.
He was acting in
an irrational manner.
I'm your Captain now.
Where am I?!
You're onboard
the Starship Enterprise.
Riker has no honor.
He tricked me!
He is only dazed, sir.
Well, that's fine,
but where's Commander Riker?
Cloaking shields off.
Obey my orders.
We will be destroyed.
If we are, it will be in battle
and I will die with you.
So, I repeat,
cloaking shields off.
WORF:
It is the Pagh, sir.
It has all armament
locked on us and ready to fire.
Hold this position.
Hailing frequencies.
Calling the Pagh,
this is the Enterprise.
We are here to assist.
Do not fire.
They will not believe you.
Pagh, we are here to assist.
Do you read me?
Enterprise,
this is Captain William Riker
of the Klingon vessel Pagh.
I order you to lower
your shields and surrender.
Lower shields.
Surrender, as ordered.
KARGAN:
I demand
to be beamed
back aboard my vessel!
Transporter Chief,
prepare to beam Captain Kargan
back aboard the Pagh.
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir.
Captain Riker, we can carry out
your repairs immediately.
Thank you, Captain Picard.
You should
have killed me.
I don't want
your command.
But you tricked me to get it.
Either way,
you can have it back.
Then return to your station.
( low growl )
Get him off my ship.
Yes, Captain.
( quietly: )
You understand
the Klingons better
than I thought,
Commander.
Thank you,
my friend.
That might have been
one of the shortest assignments
in the history of Starfleet.
Wrong, Number One.
It was almost
the longest.
Well done.
Thank you.
Actually, I learned quite a bit.
Apparently, not
when to duck.
When not to duck
would be more accurate.
Welcome aboard,
Number One.
Now, Lieutenant, conduct
the Commander to Sick Bay.
Aye, sir.
Commander?
Your little toy worked.
Thanks.
I'm glad it did.
You come from a very brave
and unique people.
I'm glad you're with us
on the Enterprise.
Thank you, Commander.
And welcome home.