Captain's Log,
Stardate 42523.7.
We are en route
to the newly established
Starbase 173 for port call.
Crew rotation is scheduled
and we will be off-loading
experiment modules.
Hold it.
That's my chair.
My luck is
always lousy
unless I start
on the dealer's right.
That would seem to be
superstition.
Bitter experience
has taught me
it's a fundamental
truth.
Okay. The game is
five-card stud
nothing wild.
Ante up.
This game is
exceedingly simple.
With only 52 cards,
21 of which I will see
and four other players
there are a limited number
of winning combinations.
There's more to this
than just the cards, Data.
But of course.
The bets will indicate the
relative strength of each hand.
Time to pluck a pigeon.
Five.
I'm in.
I, too.
Mm-hmm.
Call.
A seven
and a six.
Ladies.
I bet ten.
I'll see that.
Call.
Fold.
Yeah, me, too.
I'm out.
I bet five.
I'll see it.
Your five and five.
Too rich for me.
No help.
( players oohing )
I bet ten.
Your ten and ten.
Is that what is known
as a poker face?
Are you playing or not?
I fold.
( groans and laughter )
You had nothing.
He bluffed you, Data.
It makes very little sense
to bet when you cannot win.
But I did win.
I was betting
that you wouldn't call.
How could you tell?
PULASKI:
Instinct, Data.
Instinct.
The game is seven-card high/low
with a buy on the last card.
And just to make it
more interesting
the man with the ax takes all.
My god.
Phillipa Louvois
and back in uniform.
It's been ten years
but seeing you
again like this
makes it seem like 50.
If we weren't around
all these people
do you know what
I would like to do?
Bust a chair
across my teeth?
After that.
Oh, ain't love wonderful?
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
So, what are you
doing out here?
I am in charge of
the 23rd Sector
JAG Office.
We're brand-new.
I have no staff,
but one terrified little Ensign.
And, hopefully, we can make
some good law out here.
Anything is possible.
So you came back
to Starfleet.
Still the most
worthwhile place to be.
You had no reason
to leave.
They forced me out.
Mm.
No, that was your own
damn stubborn pride.
When I prosecuted you
in the Stargazer court-martial
I was doing my job.
Oh, you did more than your job.
You enjoyed it.
Not true.
A court-martial
is standard procedure
when a ship is lost.
I was doing my duty
as an officer of the Judge
Advocate General.
You always enjoyed
the adversarial process
more than getting
at the truth.
Well, I hope that you've learned
a little wisdom along the way.
You know, I never thought
I would say this
but it's good to see you again.
It brings a sense of order
and stability to my universe
to know that you're still
a pompous ass.
And a damn sexy man.
MAN:
Captain Picard?
Admiral.
Captain Louvois.
You're acquainted
with Captain Picard?
Oh, yes.
We're old...
friends.
Excuse me.
Picard, call me.
You can
buy me dinner.
Captain, it's good
to see you again.
Admiral.
May I present
Commander Bruce Maddox.
Commander.
He has an interesting
proposal for you,
but that can wait for awhile.
I'm eager to see the Enterprise.
Yes, sir.
This way.
RIKER:
Admiral
on the Bridge.
I was a little surprised
at the decision
to put a base in force
so close
to the Neutral Zone.
ADMIRAL:
As you know, we've
had disturbing news
from both sides of the zone.
We're here to respond
when needed.
And it won't hurt
to have the Romulans know
that we're nearby.
Ah. Well, Captain, I want to
thank you for this opportunity.
For 500 years, every ship
that has born the name
of the Enterprise
has become a legend.
This one is no different.
Admiral.
Ah, yes.
Captain, Commander Maddox is
here to work on your android.
Please take care of him.
How have you been, Data?
My condition does not alter
with the passage of time,
Commander.
Are the two of you
acquainted?
Yes, I evaluated Data
when it first applied
to the academy.
And was the sole member of the
committee to oppose my entrance
on the grounds
that I was not a sentient being.
What exactly will
this work entail?
I am going
to disassemble Data.
All right,
explain this procedure.
( clears throat )
Ever since
I first saw Data
at the entrance
evaluation
at the Starfleet Academy
I've wanted
to understand it.
I became a student of the works
of Dr. Noonien Soong,
Data's creator
and I've tried
to continue his work.
I believe I am very close
to the breakthrough
that will enable me
to duplicate Dr. Soong's work
and replicate this.
But, as a first step I must
disassemble and study it.
Data is going to be my guide.
Data?
It sounds intriguing.
How will you proceed?
I will run a full
diagnostic on Data
evaluating the condition
of its current software.
I will then dump its core memory
into the Starbase
mainframe computer
and begin a
detailed analysis
of its construction.
You've constructed
a positronic brain?
Yes.
Have you determined how
the electron resistance
across the neural filaments
is to be resolved?
Not precisely.
That would seem to be
a necessary first step.
I am confident
that I will find the answer
once I examine
the filament links
in your anterior cortex.
But, if the answer
is not forthcoming
your model will
not function.
I do not anticipate
any problems.
You seem a little vague
on the specifics.
What are the risks
to Commander Data?
Negligible.
Captain, I believe
his basic research
lacks the specifics necessary
to support
an experiment
of this
magnitude.
Commander Data is a valued
member of my Bridge crew.
Based on what I've heard,
I cannot allow Commander Data
to submit himself
to this experiment.
I was afraid this might be
your attitude, Captain.
Here are Starfleet's
transfer orders
separating Commander Data
from the Enterprise
and reassigning it
to Starbase 173
under my command.
Data, I will see you
in my office tomorrow
at 0900 hours.
( door chimes )
Come.
You sent for me, sir?
Data, please sit down.
Well, we have
a problem.
I find myself
in complete agreement
with that assessment
of the situation, sir.
Your service to this ship
has been exemplary.
I don't want to lose you.
I will not submit
to the procedure, sir.
Data...
I understand
your objections,
but I have to consider
Starfleet's interests.
What if Commander Maddox
is correct?
There is a possibility
that many more beings
like yourself
can be constructed.
Sir, Lieutenant La Forge's eyes
are far superior
to human biological eyes, true?
Mm-hmm.
Then why are not all
human officers required
to have their eyes replaced
with cybernetic implants?
I see.
It is precisely because
I am not human.
That will be all, Mr. Data.
Computer, pull
all relevant information
with regard
to Starfleet regulations
on the transfer of officers.
COMPUTER:
Working.
My God.
Twice in as many days.
I need your help.
An historic moment.
I have been trying to make sense
of this gobbledygook,
but it's beyond me.
The fact is,
my android officer, Data,
is being transferred
compulsorily
to be made part
of a highly dangerous
and ill-conceived experiment,
and I want it stopped.
He can refuse
to undergo the procedure
but we can't stop
the transfer.
Once this Maddox has...
got control
of Data
anything could happen.
I don't trust that man.
We agree to certain risks
when we join Starfleet.
Yes, acceptable risks,
justified risks
but I can't accept this.
It's unjustified.
It's unfair.
He has rights.
All this passion over a machine?
Don't start.
This is
important to me.
Is there an option?
There is always an option.
He can resign.
I see.
So you came to me for help.
Yes, I came to you.
You're the JAG Officer
for this sector.
I had no choice
but to come to you.
Wait.
I didn't mean it that way.
I'm glad you
felt you could...
well, come to me.
The word "trust" just isn't
in your vocabulary, is it?
Good try--
nine out of ten for effort.
I wish things were different.
I wish I could believe that.
"When in disgrace
with fortune and men's eyes
I all alone beweep
my outcast state."
Is it just words to you?
Or do you fathom the meaning?
Is it not customary
to request permission
before entering
an individual's quarters?
I thought that we
could talk this out.
That I could try
to persuade you.
Your memories and knowledge
will remain intact.
Reduced to the mere
facts of the events.
The substance, the
flavor of the moment
could be lost.
Take games of chance...
Games of chance?
Yes, I had read and absorbed
every treatise and textbook
on the subject
and found myself well prepared
for the experience.
Yet, when I finally
played poker
I discovered
that the reality
bore little resemblance
to the rules.
And the point being?
That, while I believe
it is possible
to download information
contained in a positronic brain
I do not believe you have
acquired the expertise necessary
to preserve the essence
of those experiences.
There is an ineffable
quality to memory
which I do not believe
can survive your procedure.
"Ineffable quality."
I had rather we had
done this together
but, one way or the other,
we are doing it.
You're under my command.
No, sir.
I am not under yours
nor anyone else's command.
I have resigned from Starfleet.
Resigned?
You can't resign.
I regret the decision,
but I must.
I am the culmination
of one man's dream.
This is not ego
or vanity,
but when Dr. Soong created me
he added to the substance
of the universe.
If, by your experiments,
I am destroyed
something unique, something
wonderful will be lost.
I cannot permit that.
I must protect
his dream.
And so must I.
But keep packing
because one way
or the other
you will be reporting.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Commander Bruce Maddox,
having been thwarted
by Data's abrupt resignation,
is now seeking a legal remedy
for his woes.
Captain Louvois
has requested my presence
at those discussions.
Your response is
emotional and irrational.
Irrational?
You are endowing Data
with human characteristics
because it looks human,
but it is not.
If it were a box on wheels
I would not be facing
this opposition.
Overt sentimentality is not one
of Captain Picard's failings.
Trust me, I know.
I will tell you again.
Data is a valued
member of my crew.
He's an outstanding
Bridge Officer.
If I am permitted to make
this experiment, the horizons
for human achievement
become boundless.
Consider, every
ship in Starfleet
with a Data on board.
Utilizing its
extraordinary capabilities,
acting as our hands and eyes
in dangerous situations.
Look, you're preaching
to the choir, here.
Why don't you get to the point?
Data must not be
permitted to resign.
Data is
a Starfleet Officer.
He still has
certain rights.
Rights, rights!
I'm sick to death
of hearing about rights.
What about my right
not to have my life work
subverted
by blind ignorance?
We have rule of law
in this Federation.
You cannot simply
seize people
and experiment with them
to prove your pet theories.
Thank you.
MADDOX:
Now you're
doing it.
Data is an extraordinary
piece of engineering
but it is a machine.
If you permit it
to resign
it will destroy years
of work in robotics.
Starfleet does not have
to allow the resignation.
Commander, who do you think
you're working for?
Starfleet is not an organization
that ignores
it's own regulations
when they become inconvenient.
Whether you like it or not,
Data does have rights.
Let me put it
another way.
Would you permit the computer
of the Enterprise
to refuse a refit?
That's an interesting point.
But the Enterprise computer
is property.
Is Data?
Of course.
( sighing ) There may be law
to support this position.
Then find it.
A ruling with such
broad-ranging implications
must be supported.
Phillipa...
I hope you will use
the same zeal
that you did in
the Stargazer court-martial.
Data, you're supposed
to rip the wrapping off.
With the application
of a little care, Wes,
the paper can be
utilized again.
Data, you're missing
the point.
The Dream of the Fire
by K'Ratak.
Thank you, Worf.
It was in the hands
of the Klingons
that the novel attained
its full stature.
I couldn't disagree more
but we'll save that argument
for another day.
DATA:
Excuse me, please.
Is something wrong?
Of course there is.
You're going away.
No one regrets that necessity
more than myself,
but you do understand
my reasons?
Sure, I understand.
I just don't like
you being forced out.
It's not fair.
As Dr. Pulaski would, at this
junction, no doubt remind us
"life is rarely fair."
Sorry, that just doesn't
make it any better.
I shall miss you, Geordi.
Yeah.
Me, too.
Take care of yourself, Data.
I have completed my research.
Based on the Acts of Cumberland
passed in the early 21st century
Data is the property
of Starfleet.
He cannot resign
and he cannot refuse
to cooperate with
Commander Maddox.
What if I challenge
this ruling?
Then I shall be required
to hold a hearing.
Then I so challenge.
Convene
your hearing.
Captain, that would be
exceedingly difficult.
This is a new base.
I have no staff.
Surely, Captain,
you have regulations
to take care
of such an eventuality.
There are.
I can use serving
officers as legal counsel.
You, as the senior officer,
would defend.
Very good.
And the unenviable task
of prosecuting this case
would fall on you, Commander
as the next most
senior officer
of the defendant's ship.
I can't.
I won't.
Data's my comrade.
We have served together.
I not only respect him,
I consider him my friend.
When people of good conscience
have an honest dispute
we must still sometimes resort
to this kind
of adversarial system.
You just want me to prove
that Data is a mere machine.
I can't do that,
because I don't believe it.
I happen to
know better
so I am neither
qualified
nor willing.
You're going to have
to find someone else.
Then I will rule summarily
based on my findings.
Data is a toaster.
Have him report immediately
to Commander Maddox
for experimental refit.
I see.
I have no choice
but to agree.
Good, and I expect you to do
your duty in that courtroom.
If I find for one minute
that you are not
doing your best
I will end this, then and there.
You don't have to remind us
of our duty.
You just...
just remember yours.
I have never forgotten it.
Not then,
and certainly not now.
( door chimes )
Come.
Data...
Captain Louvois
has issued a ruling.
You are the property
of Starfleet Command.
You cannot resign.
I see.
From limitless options
I am reduced to none,
or rather one.
I can only hope
that Commander Maddox
is more capable than
it would appear.
Data, you're not
going to submit.
We are going
to fight this.
I've challenged the ruling.
Captain Louvois will be
compelled to convene a hearing.
She may be overly attached
to the letter of the law
but I suspect that she still
understands its spirit.
We will put to rest
this question of your legal
status once and for all.
Now, I have been asked
to represent you
but if there is
some other officer
with which you would feel
more happy...
Captain, I have complete
confidence in your ability
to represent my interests.
Computer,
identify Riker, William T.
Access code theta alpha
two, seven, three, seven,
blue enable.
COMPUTER:
Riker, William T., identified.
Ready.
Access all available
technical schematics
on Lieutenant Commander Data.
Working.
This hearing,
convened
on Stardate 42527.4
is to determine the legal status
of the android known as Data.
The Office
of Judge Advocate General
has rendered a finding
of property.
The defense has challenged.
Commander Riker?
Your Honor, there
is only one issue
and one relevant
piece of evidence.
I call Lieutenant
Commander Data.
COMPUTER:
Verify Lieutenant
Commander Data.
Current assignment:
USS Enterprise.
Starfleet Command
decoration for valor.
Your Honor, we'll
stipulate to all of this.
Objection, Your Honor.
I want this read.
All of it.
Sustained.
...valor and gallantry,
Medal of Honor with clusters
Legion of Honor, the Star Cross.
LOUVOIS:
Proceed,
Commander.
Commander,
what are you?
An android.
Which is?
Webster's 24th Century
Dictionary, Fifth Edition,
defines an android
as an automaton
made to resemble a human being.
"An automaton."
Made by whom?
Sir?
Who built you, Commander?
Dr. Noonien Soong.
And he was?
The foremost authority
on cybernetics.
More basic than that.
What was he?
Human?
Thank you.
Commander, what is the capacity
of your memory
and how fast can you
access information?
I have
an ultimate storage capacity
of 800 quadrillion bits.
My total linear computational
speed has been rated
at 60 trillion operations
per second.
Your Honor, I offer
into evidence
Prosecution's Exhibit "A."
A rod of parsteel,
tensile strength 40 kilo-bars.
Commander, would
you bend that?
PICARD:
Objection.
There are many
life-forms possessed
with megastrength.
These issues are not relevant
to this hearing.
I'm afraid
I can't agree, Captain.
Proceed with your demonstration,
Commander.
Drawing on the log
of the construction
of the prototype android Lore
also constructed
by Noonien Soong
I request to be allowed
to remove the Commander's hand
for your inspection.
Objection.
It doesn't matter.
Objection withdrawn.
Proceed, Commander.
I'm sorry.
The Commander is a physical
representation of a dream
an idea conceived of
by the mind of a man.
Its purpose-- to serve human
needs and interests.
It's a collection
of neural nets
and heuristic algorithms.
Its responses dictated
by an elaborate software
written by a man.
Its hardware built
by a man.
And now...
And now a man
will shut it off.
Pinocchio is broken.
Its strings have been cut.
I request a recess.
Granted.
Do you mean his argument
was that good?
Riker's presentation
was devastating.
He almost convinced me.
Well, you've got
the harder argument.
By his own admission
Data is a machine.
Mm-hmm, that's true.
You're worried about
what's going to
happen to him?
No.
I've had to send people
on far more dangerous missions.
Well, then this should
work out fine.
Maddox could get lucky
and create a whole
army of Datas--
all very valuable.
Oh, yes, no doubt.
He's proved
his value to you.
In ways that I cannot even begin
to calculate.
And now he's about to be ruled
the property of Starfleet.
That should increase his value.
In what way?
Well, consider that,
in the history of many worlds
there have always been
disposable creatures.
They do the dirty work.
They do the work
that no one else wants to do
because it's too difficult
or too hazardous.
And an army of Datas,
all disposable...
You don't have to think
about their welfare.
You don't think
about how they feel.
Whole generations
of disposable people.
You're talking about slavery.
Oh, I think
that's a little harsh.
I don't think that's
a little harsh.
I think that's the truth.
But that's a truth
that we have obscured
behind a comfortable,
easy euphemism--
property.
But that's not the issue
at all, is it?
PICARD:
Commander Riker has
dramatically demonstrated
to this court
that Lieutenant Commander Data
is a machine.
Do we deny that?
No, because it is not relevant.
We, too, are machines,
just machines
of a different type.
Commander Riker
has also reminded us
that Lieutenant Commander
Data was created by a human.
Do we deny that? No.
Again, it is not relevant.
Children are created
from the building blocks
of their parents' DNA.
Are they property?
I call Lieutenant Commander
Data to the stand.
What are these?
My medals.
Why do you pack them?
What logical purpose
do they serve?
I do not know, sir.
I suppose none.
I just wanted them.
Is that vanity?
And this?
A gift
from you, sir.
You value it?
Yes, sir.
Why?
It is a reminder
of friendship and service.
And this?
You have no other portraits
of your fellow crew members.
Why this person?
I would prefer not
to answer that question, sir.
I gave my word.
Under the circumstances,
I don't think Tasha would mind.
She was special to me, sir.
We were...
intimate.
Thank you, Commander.
I have no further questions
for this witness.
Commander Riker,
do you want to cross?
I have no questions, Your Honor.
Thank you.
You may step down.
I call to the stand
Commander Bruce Maddox
as a hostile witness.
COMPUTER:
Verify, Maddox, Bruce,
Commander.
Current assignment:
Associate Chair of Robotics
Daystrom Technological
Institute.
Major papers...
Yes, yes, yes.
Suffice it to say
he's an expert.
Commander, it is your contention
that Lieutenant Commander Data
is not a sentient being
and, therefore, not entitled
to all the rights reserved
for all life-forms
within this Federation?
Data is not sentient, no.
Commander, would you
enlighten us?
What is required
for sentience?
Intelligence, self-awareness,
consciousness.
Prove to the court
that I am sentient.
This is absurd.
We all know you're sentient.
So I'm sentient,
but Commander Data is not?
MADDOX:
That's right.
Uh-huh.
Why?
Why am I sentient?
Well, you are self-aware.
Ah, that's the second
of your criteria.
Let's deal with the first,
intelligence.
Is Commander Data intelligent?
Yes.
It has the ability
to learn and understand
and to cope with new situations.
Like this hearing.
Yes.
What about self-awareness?
What does that mean?
Why... why am I self-aware?
Because you are conscious
of your existence and actions.
You are aware of yourself
and your own ego.
Commander Data,
what are you doing now?
I am taking part
in a legal hearing
to determine my rights
and status--
am I a person
or property?
And what's at stake?
My right to choose.
Perhaps my very life.
"My rights."
"My status."
"My right to choose."
( sighing )
"My life."
Well, he seems reasonably
self-aware to me, Commander.
I'm waiting.
This is exceedingly difficult.
Do you like Commander Data?
I...
I don't know it
well enough
to like or dislike it.
But you admire him?
Oh, yes.
It's an extraordinary piece...
Of engineering and programming.
Yes, you have said that.
Commander, you have
devoted your life
to the study of cybernetics
in general?
Yes.
And Commander Data
in particular?
Yes.
And now you propose
to dismantle him?
So that I can learn from it
and construct more.
How many more?
As many as
are needed.
Hundreds, thousands,
if necessary.
There is no limit.
A single Data
and forgive me, Commander
is a curiosity.
A wonder even.
But thousands of Datas--
isn't that becoming a race?
And won't we be judged
by how we treat
that race?
Now tell me, Commander,
what is Data?
I don't understand.
What is he?
A machine.
Is he?
Are you sure?
Yes!
You see, he's met two of your
three criteria for sentience.
So, what if he meets the third,
consciousness,
in even the smallest degree?
What is he then?
I don't know.
Do you?
Well, that's the question
you have to answer.
Your Honor, a courtroom
is a crucible.
In it, we burn away
irrelevancies
until we are left
with a pure product--
the truth-- for all time.
Now, sooner or later, this man,
or others like him
will succeed
in replicating Commander Data.
Now, the decision
you reach here today
will determine
how we will regard
this creation of our genius.
It will reveal the kind
of a people we are
what he is destined to be.
It will reach far beyond
this courtroom
and this one android.
It could significantly
redefine the boundaries
of personal liberty and freedom.
Expanding them for some
savagely curtailing them
for others.
Are you prepared to condemn him
and all who come after him
to servitude and slavery?
Your Honor, Starfleet was
founded to seek out new life.
Well, there it sits.
Waiting.
You wanted a chance to make law.
Well, here it is.
Make it a good one.
It sits there looking at me
and I don't know
what it is.
This case has dealt
with metaphysics
with questions best left
to saints and philosophers.
I'm neither competent
nor qualified to answer those.
But I've got
to make a ruling
to try to speak to the future.
Is Data a machine? Yes.
Is he the property
of Starfleet?
No.
We have all been
dancing around
the basic issue--
does Data have a soul?
I don't know
that he has.
I don't know that I have.
But I have got
to give him the freedom
to explore
that question himself.
It is the ruling
of this court
that Lieutenant Commander Data
has the freedom
to choose.
I formally refuse
to undergo your procedure.
I will cancel
that transfer order.
Thank you.
And, Commander,
continue your work.
When you are ready,
I will still be here.
I find some
of what you propose...
intriguing.
He's remarkable.
You didn't call him "it."
You see, sometimes
it does work.
Phillipa.
Dinner?
You buying?
Sir, there is a celebration
on the holodeck.
I have no right
to be there.
Because you failed in your task?
No, God, no.
I came that close
to winning, Data.
Yes, sir.
I almost cost you your life.
Is it not true...
that had you
refused to prosecute
Captain Louvois would
have ruled summarily against me?
Yes.
That action injured you
and saved me.
I will not forget it.
You're a wise man, my friend.
Not yet, sir
but, with your help,
I am learning.
♪♪