Sir, we are approaching
Klavdia 3.
Take us to impulse power.
Aye, sir.
Impulse power.
Bridge, this is engineering.
PICARD:
Yes, Lieutenant.
Now that we're out of warp,
I'd like to use this time
to make some
routine adjustments
on the deuterium
control conduit.
We're overdue.
How much time will these
adjustments require, Lieutenant?
LA FORGE:
A couple of hours, sir.
Proceed,
Lieutenant La Forge.
Standard orbit, Ensign.
Wes, I'm gonna need an
S-C-M, model three,
from ship stores.
Can you handle that?
Right away.
All right.
Magnify, Mr. Worf.
Hardly an inviting planet.
Even for a research
establishment.
I would have thought
the inhabitants of Daled 4
would send a future leader to a
more hospitable environment.
For some, security
is more important than comfort.
Yes, but 16 years.
WORF:
Captain, we are being hailed.
Hailing frequencies, Mr. Worf.
Open.
This is Captain Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
( distorted transmission )
Sir, the planet's troposphere
is distorting our signal.
Can you clean that up,
Mr. Worf?
I'll try.
Now.
This is Picard
of the Enterprise.
Please, will you repeat
your message?
FEMALE VOICE:
I am Anya.
Have you come for
Salia of Daled 4?
That is correct.
ANYA:
What species are you?
Human.
ANYA:
Excellent.
Bring us aboard.
That is all.
Friendly, isn't she?
Friendly or not, Salia has
the rank of head of state.
So, we shall treat her
and Anya accordingly.
Number One, Mr. Worf,
let's go greet our visitors.
You have the bridge,
Mr. Data.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
Welcome to the Enterprise.
I'm Captain Picard.
This is Salia of Daled 4.
I didn't
feel a thing.
Is that normal when one
is transported, Captain?
Oh, yes, it is.
Those must be the matter-
energy conversion controls.
May I take a look?
Yes, of course.
I could arrange for a tour
of the ship, if you'd like.
Oh, I'd love that.
No, that will not
be necessary.
Just show us to
our quarters, Captain Picard.
Very well.
We're accomodating you in
quarters normally reserved
for Starfleet admiralty.
I'm sure you'll find them
quite comfortable.
That's a superconducting
magnet, isn't it?
Yeah, it's an S-C-M model...
How did you know that?
Study. For the last
16 years that's all I've--
Please, Salia.
Walk ahead with me.
Better be careful.
Those can rip the iron
right out of your blood cells.
Commander, who is she?
Uh, I think she's
a governess.
No, the girl.
Oh, I don't know if she'll
have time for you, Wes.
She's destined to
rule an entire world.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
( door chime )
Come in.
You wanted to see me?
Yes.
Data, the girl
who came on board...
Salia of Daled 4.
Who is she?
Little is known.
She was born on Daled 4.
Her parents were
from opposite sides
in a civil war
which has lasted for centuries.
They both died shortly
after her birth.
A Federation ship brought her
and her governess to Klavdia 3
so that she could be raised
in a neutral environment.
And now, she's returning?
It is hoped she will unite
the factions and bring peace.
LA FORGE:
Ensign Crusher, report.
Are you all right?
Geordi?
Yeah, I'm fine. I just--
LA FORGE: Wes, we're waiting
for that magnet.
I'm on my way.
Captain, we've
broke in orbit
and laid in a course
for Daled 4.
And we will remain
on impulse power
until Lieutenant La Forge
completes his adjustments.
Mr. Worf, have our
passengers accomodations
met with their approval?
I doubt if anything ever meets
with that woman's approval, sir.
Captain, I'm concerned
about our new passengers.
Their emotions
do not fit
who they are and
what they're doing.
Are you suggesting they're
not who they say they are?
Actually, no.
It's more like
they're not what
they say they are.
Picard, Salia's quarters.
SALIA: Yes?
May we turn on the viewer?
Yes, of course.
PICARD: Are your
quarters satisfactory?
Yes. Very.
Tell me, Captain,
who was the young man
I met before?
That was Ensign
Wesley Crusher.
Thank you for checking
on us, Captain.
I only hope our quarters in
Daled 4 will be this luxurious.
Please feel free
to contact me at any time.
Picard out.
TROI: What I sensed
before hasn't changed.
DATA:
What puzzles me, Captain,
is how is she expected to
bring peace to Daled 4?
Its inhabitants
have been fighting
throughout their
recorded history.
What do we know about
the cause of these wars?
Only that it is the difference
between night and day.
Data, you used
a colloquialism.
Did I?
What I meant, sir,
is that Daled 4
rotates only once
per revolution.
Therefore, one side
is constantly dark
and the other side
constantly light.
One might surmise
that the two hemispheres
have developed
disparate cultures--
which is a major cause
of most wars.
( sighs )
And this child
is supposed to bring
them together.
She seems too delicate
for such a task.
Do not be fooled by her looks.
The body is just a shell.
How can I be a leader
if I don't know
anything about my people?
You will lead because you
are accepted by both sides.
And because it is
in your blood.
What is expected of me
once I'm there?
You will know.
How?
You just will.
Salia, you must arrive
with an open mind
without preconceived ideas
of the worlds you will find
or the people
on either side.
It's very frustrating.
You feel the weight of
so much responsibility.
You're not sure
you'll live up
to everyone's
expectations.
It's not only that.
Nobody has even asked me if
this is something I want.
It is your duty.
Then I have no choice.
It won't be as bad
as you think.
In fact, it could be
quite wonderful.
Besides...
you are the last
and only chance.
( chittering )
Don't you think I'm going
to need more than instinct
to do whatever is expected
of me on Daled 4?
Energy depletion level?
COMPUTER:
.04% and increasing.
Wesley?
Wesley, you haven't found
that defocused area yet?
I'm looking.
Yeah, I see the way
you're looking.
Wesley!
What?
Sorry.
I've got my mind
on something.
I can see that.
It's this girl
they beamed up, Geordi.
She's perfect.
Absolutely perfect.
Now I understand
why you can't concentrate.
I'll do better.
Okay.
( alarm sounding )
COMPUTER: Warning--
resonant field applied.
What is it?
What happened?
Uh, nothing, I had it
on the wrong setting.
( sighs )
I suppose it had
to happen to you.
It usually does
about this age.
What usually does?
Glands erupting with hormones.
Happens to all of us.
Just because I said that
I think she's interesting...
You said she was perfect.
Uh-uh.
Come on down.
You're no use around
here for now.
Come on down
from there.
Go talk to her.
Use the ladder.
That's silly, Geordi.
But, since you
recommended it,
how should I approach her?
If she'll talk to me,
what should I say?
Just say,
"Hi. I'm Wesley Crusher.
I'd like to talk to you."
And then what?
Whatever occurs to you.
Well, what if nothing
occurs to me--
Look, Wes, I don't
have time for this.
You're gonna have to
ask somebody else.
Okay.
( screaming )
That is how the
Klingon lures a mate.
Are you telling me
to go yell at Salia?
No.
Men do not roar.
Women roar.
Then they hurl
heavy objects...
and claw at you.
WESLEY:
What does the man do?
He reads love poetry.
He ducks a lot.
Worf, sounds like it works
great for the Klingons,
but I think I need to try
something a little less...
dangerous.
Then go to her door.
Beg like a human.
DATA: It should be
that simple, Wesley.
Judging by her appearance,
it is likely
you and Salia are
biologically compatible.
Of course, there could
be a difference
in the
histocompatibility complex
of the cell membrane but--
Data, I wanna meet her,
not dissect her.
Picard to Salia's quarters.
SALIA:
Yes, Captain?
May I activate the viewscreen?
Hurry. Go, go.
Certainly.
We've invited Anya
to take a tour of the ship.
Maybe you would
like to join her?
Very much.
Your escort will go
with you shortly.
Picard out.
I think I'll go on the tour.
Why can't I?
( chittering )
This is the only chance
I'll ever have
to see a vessel like this.
No.
You must remain here
where it is safe.
Salia, do an old woman a favor,
and obey me
for the rest of this trip.
You are no more an old woman
than I am a leader.
( chime )
Yes, come in.
I'm here to escort you
on a tour of the Enterprise.
ANYA:
Salia will remain behind.
I will be
right there.
You are a leader
and I am older
than you could ever imagine.
What should I say?
How do-- how do I act?
What do I do?
Guinan, I need your help.
Could you step
over here a minute?
Sounds simple enough.
Now, the first words
out of your mouth
are the most important.
You may wanna start
with something like this.
You are the most beautiful
woman in the galaxy.
But that might not work.
Yes.
Yes, it would.
You don't know how long
I've wanted to tell you that.
But you were afraid.
Yes.
Of me?
Of us, of what
we might become.
Commander...
Or that you might think
that was a line.
Maybe I do think
it's a line.
Then you think
I'm not sincere?
I didn't say that.
There's nothing
wrong with a line.
It's like a knock
at the door.
RIKER:
Then you're inviting me in?
GUINAN:
I'm not sending you away.
RIKER:
That's more than I expected.
Is it as much
as you hoped?
To hope is to recognize
the possibility.
I had only dreams.
Dreams can
be dangerous.
Not these dreams.
I dream of a galaxy
where your eyes
are the stars and the universe
worships the night.
( sighs )
Careful.
Putting me
on a pedestal so high,
you may not be able
to reach me.
Then I'll learn how to fly.
You're the heart in my day,
and the soul in my night.
I don't think
this is my style.
Shut up, kid.
Tell me more about my eyes.
WORF: This is the
dilithium crystal chamber.
Ah, our chief engineer,
Geordi La Forge.
What is that?
What are you doing?
Nothing to be concerned about.
Just performing some
routine adjustments.
I wasn't aware that the
deuterium control conduit
required routine
adjustments.
I perform
periodic inspections
on all engineering systems.
In this case, you seem to
have found a malfunction.
It's not a malfunction.
It's simply that a minute
defocused area is developed.
Lowers our operating
efficiency.
It could also lead to
excess pion production.
Our computer
would detect that.
Unless, of course,
it, too, is malfunctioning.
Look, I really have
to get this finished.
WORF:
Anya.
Please, come with me.
I will be back to
check your progress.
Ensign Crusher,
what can I do for you?
Nothing.
Is there a problem?
No.
Could you show me how to
work the food dispenser?
Sure.
Really, it's quite simple.
You just tell the
computer what you want
and it prepares
it for you.
Oh.
What should I order?
I don't know.
What do you like?
I'd like something sweet.
I know.
Computer,
Thalian chocolate mousse.
It's a wonderful sensation.
On Thalos 7, they age
the beans 400 years.
You've been there?
It's one of
my favorite places.
Oh, it must be fun to
visit a planet like that.
It's the best part of
being on the Enterprise.
I've studied about
some of them.
But to see them,
that would be wonderful.
Tell me about some of the
other places you've been.
Oh, there's too many.
The only world I've known
is Klavdia 3.
It's about time
we changed that.
How?
Come with me.
PULASKI: I'll be
with you in a moment.
What's wrong with him?
Andronesian encephalitis.
That disease is contagious.
Very unlikely.
Our air filtering system--
But there is a chance.
If you mean mathematically, yes,
the probability is not zero.
I cannot rely on
your primitive technologies.
Kill the patient.
What?
Destroy the patient.
Immediately.
Now, you calm down.
If you won't take action,
then I will.
( growling )
( gasps )
Security to sickbay.
Hurry!
PICARD:
Wait.
Hold your fire.
PICARD:
Worf!
What is she?
Keep her away.
Do not interfere.
She wants to kill Hennesey.
His disease
threatens Salia.
Captain, there is
no chance of contagion.
The situation
is under control.
ANYA:
That's not good enough.
But it will have to be.
Your powers are infinitesimal
compared to mine.
Yes, that may be.
But you will obey my orders.
You will remain in your quarters
and in your present form
for the rest of this voyage.
Is that clear?
Very.
Keep her under guard.
Aye, sir.
WORF:
Wait for me.
What kind of
creature is she?
I've never seen
anything like her.
PULASKI: There is
mention in the galactic
zoological catalogue of a
species called allasomorph
which is supposed to possess
the power to alter
their molecular structure
into other life-forms.
Such a creature would make
a perfect protector.
I want a security team
stationed outside
sickbay, Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
Captain, what if
Anya transforms?
Improvise.
Can a place so remarkable
truly exist?
Yes.
There are many more.
All of them
are different.
I've learned about them.
That's all I did on
Klavdia 3, was learn.
I know so much,
but I've seen so little.
Think of all you have
to look forward to.
This is a great
time to be alive.
For you.
For both of us.
This is all
just beginning.
We've only charted
19% of our galaxy.
The rest is out there
just waiting.
Look what we've
already discovered.
I have never seen
anything so wondrous.
Wait.
Computer, Rosseau 5.
( gasps )
Hey!
It's breathtaking.
Yes.
And you've been
to this place?
Someday, you'll visit
Rosseau 5,
and many other places,
all more spectacular.
If only it were possible.
Listen.
( ethereal whirring )
What is it?
In a moment,
the harmonic resonance
from the neutrino clouds
will become synchronous.
( ethereal whirring )
It's so beautiful.
It's like this place
has a voice.
It's trying to
speak to us.
Thank you for sharing
all of this with me.
Someday, you'll see it
all for yourself.
Look over there.
Remain here.
You are restricted
to these quarters
for the remainder
of this voyage.
You are the protector
of this ship, are you not?
I'm in charge
of security.
You must understand
my duties as well.
If you confine me to this cell,
I cannot protect Salia.
There is no need
for concern.
She is safe
on this ship.
You must understand that I
cannot make such an assumption.
You no longer
have the choice.
You have to trust me
to protect her.
No.
A true protector
cannot have two charges.
Your responsibility
is to the ship.
My duty is to Salia.
My responsibility to the ship
includes protecting Salia.
You know I'm stronger than you.
I was unprepared.
You underestimated me
in your sickbay.
That is usually fatal.
Still, you are here,
confined to your room.
I ceased my struggle
by choice,
not because of
you or your captain.
I would have
stopped you.
If not me,
someone else.
No, you cannot control me.
We will see.
We've obviously brought a very
dangerous life-form on board.
I want to minimize the
chance of any incident.
Whatever kind of
life-form Anya is,
emotionally, she's
Salia's mother.
( sighs )
The most dangerous animal
is a mother protecting
her young.
Exactly.
Captain, this is Anya.
Yes?
Salia is gone.
Where is she?
This has all been
so wonderful.
I'm not even
sure it's real.
Believe me, Ten Forward
isn't an illusion.
Not that.
I mean the way I feel.
You won't find a better dish
of chocolate anywhere.
I'm sure I won't.
Is something wrong?
I've had a great time
being with you, Wesley.
And that makes you sad?
When I was on Klavdia 3
all I could think about was
leaving that isolation.
What makes me sad is
having to face it again
after seeing what else
is possible.
Is that what awaits
you on Daled 4?
Isolation?
Yes.
I thought you were
going there
to reunite two
warring parties.
What else do you know?
Very little.
The ship's computer
doesn't have that much
on Daled 4.
How will you stop
the fighting?
I'm not certain.
I only know I will have
many responsibilities
when I get there.
Your language has no word
for the position I'll hold.
In many ways, I'll have
even less freedom
than I did
on Klavdia 3.
You could stay.
On the Enterprise?
Why not?
Because I can't.
Just because
a girl runs out
doesn't mean she doesn't
wish you to follow.
What is it?
What happened?
Salia.
Stay away from me.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
I can't stay here.
I can't have this life.
I want it
more than anything
but I can't have it.
Salia, nothing
is impossible.
Not for you.
There's a way.
I know there is.
Leave her alone!
Ensign, step
away from her.
ANYA:
Come with me.
Energy depletion level.
COMPUTER:
Zero.
La Forge to bridge.
PICARD:
Yes, Lieutenant?
I've just completed
my final adjustments.
Thanks for the time.
You now have warp
engines available.
PICARD:
Very good.
Number One, get us to Daled
as quickly as possible.
Ensign Gibson,
take us to warp 8.8.
Warp 8.8, sir.
Estimated time?
Three hours,
nine minutes.
Ensign Crusher, when you are
finished with your duties
in engineering,
report to my ready room.
WESLEY:
Yes, sir.
You have the bridge,
Number One.
RIKER:
Aye, sir.
The woman, Anya,
is not what she
appears to be.
She is an allasomorph.
A shapeshifter?
Yes.
She's not only
a governess,
she's also the
girl's protector.
Now, I don't care to interfere
in the personal relationships
of those under my command.
But in this case...
You want me to
stay away from Salia.
Yes, I do.
For the good of the ship
and the safety of
everyone on board.
I will do as you ask.
Why won't you let
me have a friend?
It is my duty to protect
you from danger.
There's no danger here.
There is always danger from
one who is not your kind.
Salia, he's confusing you.
You're forgetting
your responsibilities.
Whether or not I see Wesley
is for me to decide.
It is not.
I raised you,
I protected you,
and I intend to deliver you
to Daled 4.
Maybe what you want
doesn't matter anymore.
Salia, please.
I know it's
difficult for you.
But you must do what you are
destined to do.
PICARD:
Standard orbit.
Aye, sir.
Hailing frequencies,
Mr. Worf.
Captain, I'm encountering
the same interference
we experienced on Klavdia 3.
DATA: The troposphere appears
to be distorting our signals.
It is fascinating, Captain.
Klavdia 3 and Daled 4
have almost identical
atmospheres.
Magnify.
Times 20.
How could anyone exist
in an environment
so totally hostile
toward human life?
Mr. Data, do whatever
is necessary
to override the interference.
Let's complete our mission.
( chime )
Come in.
Salia.
You shouldn't
have come.
Do you want me to leave?
I didn't say that.
Then you want me to stay.
Does Anya know
you're here?
That doesn't matter.
I'm glad you came.
I thought Anya would have
kept you with her.
I have certain rights.
So, in other words,
you slipped out.
While she was asleep.
I hope you didn't get in
trouble from your captain.
Oh, I haven't gotten
in trouble yet.
Anya thought you
would corrupt me.
With my wild way of life?
Maybe...
with the normal
things people do
when they like
each other.
( growling )
Wesley, get out
of here now!
What's going on?
Just go, please.
Security, crew quarters.
( growling )
No!
Anya, no!
You should not
have disobeyed me.
I had to.
I warned you to
leave her alone.
Captain's log,
stardate 42568.8.
Since Anya's powers
of transformation
apparently gave her the ability
to escape her guards unnoticed,
we have sealed her quarters
with a forcefield
that will contain her
no matter how small a form
she may take.
Captain, I'm receiving
an audio signal.
Audio on.
MAN:
Come in, Enterprise.
This is command headquarters
of Daled four.
We have been expecting you.
Sir, sensors indicate the
communication originated
from a terawatt
source on the planet.
That's more power than our
entire ship can generate.
It is what is needed to
penetrate the atmosphere.
Which means we lack the
ability to respond, sir.
Sir, there are beam-down
coordinates encoded
within the carrier signal.
Splendid.
I'll arrange
for our guest to beam down.
Forcefield off.
( chime )
Come in.
We have arrived.
Salia will be with you
in just a moment.
You're not going?
No.
My duties have
been completed.
I have done all that I could.
I hope it
was enough.
You've raised me well,
and I thank you for that.
I would not have
harmed the boy.
I only wanted to frighten him.
I know.
You are ready for
what awaits you,
and you will do well.
I know I've been
hard on you.
But I wanted
to prepare you
for anything you might
be required to do.
Will I ever be able
to leave Daled 4?
Probably not.
But anything
is possible.
That's what Wes said.
I hope he's right.
Where will you go?
The third moon is within range
of this ship's transporter.
I shall go there.
It was my home
before we went away.
I'm going to miss you.
I know.
I am ready now.
I will escort you to
transporter room six.
You will be happy
to see me leave.
No.
You are
a worthy opponent.
Thank you.
At heart, we are
very much alike.
Yes, we are.
Perhaps we shall
fight again.
On the same side?
It would be an honor.
Shall we go?
( chime )
Come in.
Wesley, I have to go now.
Was it fun?
What do you mean?
Playing humanoid.
Was it fun?
Wesley, look at me.
Right now, this minute,
this is what I am.
A humanoid girl.
What are you really?
Does it matter?
Yes.
Our natural state is one
unlike anything you can imagine.
So, you took this form
for our benefit?
That's why you wanted to know
what species we are.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
I didn't mean to.
I loved you.
I love you, too.
Can you?
Yes!
Oh, yes!
I have the same feelings,
the same emotions as you.
You must believe me.
Please go.
Wesley, let's not say
good-bye like this.
Prepare to beam Salia
to the specified coordinates.
Aye, sir.
Our world is grateful
for the courtesy
which you have
extended us.
I hope some day
that the Federation
and Daled 4 will have
formal contact.
That is my
wish as well.
Coordinates have
been input, sir.
Proceed.
Wait.
A taste to remember me by.
I wish there was something
I could give you.
You already have.
I'm glad you came
to say good-bye.
Thank you for everything.
I want you to leave now.
Why?
I cannot arrive in my
planet in this form,
and I want you to
remember me as I am now.
Don't worry.
I will.
Energize.
( sighs )
( laughter and conversation )
Seeing her on the
transporter pad,
it was like
seeing pure light.
I miss her.
I feel... empty.
I know that sensation.
But there'll come
a time when
all you'll remember
is the love.
I'm never gonna feel this
way about anyone else.
You're right.
I didn't expect you
to say that.
There'll be others.
But every time you feel love,
it'll be different.
Every time
it's different.
Knowing that doesn't make it
any easier.
It's not supposed to.