Captain's log,
stardate 42609.1.
In response to a desperate
plea from my old friend
Captain Donald Varley
of the USS Yamato,
I am running a grave risk
by taking the Enterprise
into the neutral zone.
Varley's request was prompted
by dangerous malfunctions
which have been plaguing
our sister ship.
Perhaps with both crews
working together,
we can eliminate
the problems
before our presence is
detected by the Romulans.
How long to rendezvous,
Mr. Crusher?
Four minutes
and 33 seconds, sir.
Status of download,
Mr. Data?
The Yamato log should be in our
computer by rendezvous, sir.
Have you nailed down
our little hiccup yet?
Sir?
The odd reading?
No, sir. It might be
due to problems
currently being
experienced by the Yamato.
Trouble,
number one?
I'm not sure, sir.
Are we alone out here, Worf?
Yes sir, there are
no other vessels in the area
except the Yamato.
Which is coming into
visual range now.
At last.
WORF:
Transmission from
the Yamato, sir.
On viewer.
Donald?
What's a nice Starfleet
captain like you doing
doing in a place
like this?
It's good to see you
again, Jean-Luc.
Despite your
antique humor.
I only hope your people
are able to help us.
The malfunctions are
becoming serious.
We lost an engineering team
when the computer
shut down a forcefield
in an open shuttle bay.
18 people.
Do you have any idea
what caused this, sir?
None. They're affecting
every system simultaneously.
It's like the ship has suddenly
decided to fall apart.
It's beginning
to make me think that
we should've run these
galaxy class ships
across a few more drawing boards
before building one.
You believe
it's a design flaw?
I don't know.
I'm grasping
at straws here.
All I know is
we've got to get it fixed
before I lose more than
an engineering team.
Do you wish to evacuate
any non-essential personnel
to the Enterprise, sir?
No. No that would be
premature.
Donald, we'll get our teams
to work on it immediately.
I'm sure neither of us
feels too comfortable
sitting around in
the neutral zone.
I know what
you're thinking--
what the hell am I
doing here?
Well I heard a...
few rumors about a couple
of archaeological digs
that started
making the Iconians
sound a lot less
like legend.
I did a little
investigating,
and I located
their home world.
In the neutral zone?
In the neutral zone.
Donald, that was
quite a risk to run
to satisfy archaeological
curiosity.
The risk would be in allowing
the Romulans to locate Iconia.
( static )
--fortunately,
I got there first.
It's a virtually
dead planet,
but enough
technology remains
to give the Romulans an edge
if they should find it.
( static )
Donald, your transmission
is breaking up.
Mr. Data,
try and clean that up.
Sir, there is
an energy build-up
in the Yamato's
engineering section.
Yamato, this is
the Enterprise.
Yamato, come in.
Captain, magnetic seals in the
antimatter chamber are decaying.
Captain...
Donald, come in!
Shields up.
Sir.
DATA:
Sensors indicate...
no life reading, sir.
WORF: Captain,
another vessel
is coming within
sensor range.
It is Romulan.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's log,
supplemental.
The Yamato's entire crew
and their families,
more than a thousand people,
have been lost.
Circumstances
unfortunately
permit us
no pause for grief.
No response from
the Romulan vessel.
Arm phasers and prepare
to lock on target.
Did they attack
the Yamato?
Unknown, sir.
All their weapons systems
have been fully activated.
Still no response.
Romulan vessel, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
Captain Picard.
Explain your illegal presence
in the Neutral Zone.
Explain yours.
Are you responsible for the
destruction of the Yamato ?
No, but believe me,
Captain,
had we chosen
to exercise our right
to defend
the Neutral Zone,
we would not have stopped
with one starship.
You will leave at once.
Comments?
She's extremely
anxious.
Understandable if she just
destroyed a federation starship.
Your scan was
inconclusive,
we don't know what
happened to the Yamato.
Our presence
in the Neutral Zone
is provocative.
It could force her
to respond.
Open.
We will comply
when I have determined the cause
of the destruction of the Yamato
and when I am fully satisfied
that you are not responsible.
Picard out.
They're engaging
their cloaking device.
Good. They can't fire
when they're cloaked.
Unless they have overcome
that deficiency.
The Yamato was destroyed
while they were cloaked.
Enough.
Answers.
I want answers,
not conjecture
Number one,
I want them
at a staff meeting
in one hour.
RIKER:
Aye, sir.
Sensor recordings reveal
that what we witnessed
was an uncontrolled
and catastrophic
matter/antimatter mix.
The magnetic seals between
the chambers collapsed and...
PICARD:
Wait...wait.
That's not possible.
Yes sir, it is, but a highly
improbable set of circumstances
has to take place for
such a result to occur.
Explain.
Okay. In the event of
a breach of seal integrity,
there's an emergency
release system
which dumps
the antimatter.
Apparently
such a dump began,
was then halted,
and the containment
seals were dropped.
There was still sufficient
antimatter present to lead
to an explosion.
And so there is
no evidence
that a weapon was used?
No, sir, none.
However it happened,
the Yamato did it
to herself.
Theorize.
What could have caused
such a catastrophic malfunction?
Well, I think Captain Varley
may have been right.
There may be
a design flaw.
In a galaxy class
starship?
Yes, sir.
It's the most sophisticated
piece of machinery ever built.
Something could have
been overlooked.
Knowing where
the flaw is located,
can you isolate the problem
and solve it?
We're already
working on it, sir.
Pull any personnel
you can use.
If we have established
that the Romulans were
not responsible for
the destruction of the Yamato,
would it not be
prudent to withdraw?
If it is a design flaw,
we're better
to stay where we are
and give Geordi time
to work on it,
or what happened to the Yamato
could happen to us.
Computer,
access Captain Donald Varley's
personal log.
Search parameter.
Locate entries
containing words
"Romulan" and-or "Iconian."
COMPUTER:
Working.
Personal log.
It was kind of Dr. Ramsey
to allow me to carry away
my own little piece
of legend
from the archaeological
dig on Denius 3.
My engineers have
examined it
but are completely baffled
by its technology.
What was its purpose?
I'm like a caveman
confronted by a tricorder.
I'm certain
this device is Iconian,
but how far had it traveled
before it was abandoned
on this alien world?
Personal log.
A galactic Rosetta Stone.
The starfields
on the artifact
were unintelligible
until I took into account
200 millennia
of stellar drift.
After that, it was easy
to pinpoint Iconia.
My first officer is
questioning the wisdom
of my order to violate
the Neutral Zone,
but I'm convinced that I've
taken the only proper course.
Should this
advanced technology
fall into the hands
of the Romulans,
we might as well
dock our ships
and defend ourselves
with sticks.
Personal log.
We've been spotted
by a Romulan cruiser.
But after playing
hide and seek
through several
solar systems,
I think I've managed
to elude them.
The Iconian probe scan--
was it an attempt at
communication?
If only I knew what
we were dealing with here.
Personal log.
I'm unable to send an away team
to the surface of Iconia,
nor can I scan the energy source
on the planet
because of these
maddening systems failures.
It's infuriating to be stopped
at the threshold of a dream
by one's own ship.
We're leaving orbit
to rendezvous with Picard.
If his people can't help us
repair the Yamato,
I must convince him
to continue
this exploration.
The future well-being
of the Federation
may well depend upon it.
COMPUTER:
No further entries
conforming to search
parameters.
Mr. Data,
there was a reference in
Captain Varley's personal log
to a probe that
scanned the Yamato.
Aye, sir. We have
a visual record.
Put it on main viewer.
What the devil is that?
Have you seen anything
like that before?
No, sir. It appears
to be a scanner,
possibly a transmitter.
Transmitting what?
Unknown, sir.
Engineering.
La Forge.
PICARD:
What progress on
the matter/antimatter scan?
Everything continues
to check out.
I'm starting an analysis
on the magnetic coils.
When the Yamato was
probed, where was she?
In orbit
around a planet
at coordinates
227 mark 359, sir.
ETA at warp factor eight?
DATA:
12 hours,
16 minutes, sir.
Sir, that would put us
substantially close
to the Romulan side
at the Neutral Zone.
That can't be helped.
Ensign,
lay in a course.
Warp factor eight.
Aye, sir.
We're going to assume
the Yamato's mission.
And risk a war?
Perhaps... prevent one.
( door chime )
Come.
Sir, may I speak
with you a moment?
Yes, of course.
Well, what is it, Wesley?
It's about
the Iconians, sir.
I was told they were
just a myth.
China was thought
to be a myth
until Marco Polo
traveled there.
No, the Iconians are
certainly real.
Sit down.
We know that three systems
within this sector
had a number of cultural
similarities.
Similarities which
can only be explained
by there being a single
unifying influence.
So they colonized
those worlds?
Probably conquered.
You mean
they were warlike?
Perhaps.
Ancient texts did
speak of...
demons of air
and darkness.
Air and darkness?
Legend has it
that they...
traveled without
the benefit of spaceships.
Merely appearing
out of thin air
on distant planets.
Sounds like magic.
Well, we would appear magical
to Stone Age people.
How did you find
all this out?
Archaeology has been
a hobby of mine
since academy days,
but why don't we talk about
what really
brought you here?
It's the Yamato,
captain.
I can't stop
thinking about her.
All those people...
dead.
I don't know how
you and commander Riker
and Geordi,
how you handle it
so easily.
Easily?
Oh no, not easily.
We handle it because
we're trained to.
As you will be.
Tea. Earl gray. Hot.
But if ever
the time comes
when the death
of a single individual
fails to move us...
Didn't you order
tea, sir?
Now that should not
have happened.
Captain's log,
supplemental.
As happened
with our sister ship,
the Enterprise is beginning
to experience
a series
of system failures.
So far they are random,
but I fear they could be
early symptoms
of what happened
to the Yamato.
PICARD:
Engineering.
La Forge.
Lieutenant,
are you making any progress
towards solving
our problems?
LA FORGE:
Solving them, no, sir,
but I can eliminate one worry.
It is not
a design flaw.
I've been reviewing
the Yamato's log.
And I think
that alien probe
may have had something to do
with their problems.
PICARD:
How?
I'd need to see
the thing.
If it was the probe,
that explains
the Yamato.
But how do you account
for the difficulties
the Enterprise is
experiencing?
I can't.
PICARD:
Lieutenant, are
our problems likely
to attain the seriousness
as those on the Yamato?
If you're asking
for speculation, I'd say
yes, sir, they are.
I need time.
Mr. La Forge,
time is one thing
we do not have
in abundance.
PICARD:
Analysis, Mr. Data?
Scanning, sir.
Well, Mr. Data?
No life-form readings, sir.
All major cities have
been heavily damaged.
And the pattern
of destruction
is that consistent
with large-scale
orbital
bombardment.
How long ago?
Approximately
200,000 years, sir.
There is an energy source
in the mountains
of the smaller continent.
PICARD:
Magnify.
Is that Iconia?
Captain Varley died
believing that it was.
RIKER:
Did you see that?
Captain, projectile launched
from the planet's surface.
Its size and composition
match the probe which
scanned the Yamato, sir.
Shields up.
Prepare a tractor beam.
Mr. La Forge, I'm going
to assist you in your research.
A probe has been launched
from Iconia.
I'm going
to capture it.
No, sir, wait!
Captain! Captain!
Coming through!
Bridge.
( grunting )
Emergency stop!
Stop it, damn it!
Tractor beam ready, sir.
Geordi,
are you all right?
Destroy the probe sir,
quickly.
Worf, target phasers.
Phasers locked
on target.
Fire.
( sighs )
welcome to the bridge,
Mr. La Forge.
Thank you, sir.
If that thing had
managed to scan us,
we never would've had
any chance of saving
the Enterprise.
That probe was
a transmitter
sending an alien
computer program,
the same program that is
currently aboard the Enterprise
trying to rewrite our software
in its own image.
We have two completely
incompatible computer systems
trying to interact.
So that's why
the ship's instruments
have become so erratic.
Yes.
What can you do?
Not very much.
The Iconian program is
so sophisticated
I may never
understand it.
Consider, Captain,
this program has
entered an alien database,
ours, and in
less than seven hours
has managed to not only
learn our systems
but has begun
to reprogram our computer.
And so the earlier probe
was responsible for
the Yamato's destruction?
Yes, but only inasmuch as
it was the probe that
transmitted the program.
But we weren't scanned
by that probe.
Then how did this thing get
aboard the Enterprise?
DATA:
We downloaded
the Yamato log.
And contained in the log was
the program.
Why didn't we suffer
the same fate?
The program affected
all of the Yamato's
systems simultaneously.
But with us,
it was deposited within
a specific section
of our mainframe.
So it's having to work its way
out from that location.
That gives us
a little breathing space.
Not much.
The injury reports are
increasing, too, sir.
Dr. Pulaski is unwilling
to trust the turbolifts.
She is sending medical teams
through the access tunnels.
Captain--
the Enterprise
computer system
is a lot like
our own bodies,
with voluntary
and involuntary systems.
Now, probably 90% of
what goes on in this ship
is done automatically,
completely
out of our control.
We're sitting on a bomb
that could go off
any second
or maybe never.
The biobeds aren't
working.
The ship is falling apart.
I've had 35 emergency calls
scattered across 12 decks.
My trauma teams are being
run ragged trying to respond.
Biobeds!
Dr. Pulaski.
Yes?
I've got a problem here.
The knitter
isn't working.
Oh, try a splint.
Doctor?
Splint, it's a very
ancient concept.
You take two flat pieces
of wood or plastic, a bandage.
The broken limb is
kept immobile.
That's crazy, that's
not practicing medicine.
Oh yes, it is,
it's a time-honored way
to practice medicine
with your head and your heart
and your hands,
so jump to it.
Damn.
Try a bypass on the shield
control interface.
No, no go.
Let me see if I can directly
access the master program.
Data.
Yes?
What happened?
Any answer would be
mere speculation.
This is yet another example
of how our actions
have random results.
Thanks, Data.
I noticed.
Life support has failed
on decks 7 and 13, sir.
Now what if this thing manages
to rewrite our entire system?
It's so far beyond us,
we have no hope of
ever understanding it,
let alone controlling it.
Our own ignorance
could kill us.
We may never...
we may never
reach that point.
A variation of what
happened to the Yamato
might destroy us first.
So we just sit here
and watch our ship
disintegrate
around us?
The probe was
launched from Iconia...
probably from
an automated system.
There may be records
near the launch site
that could help us
find a solution.
I'll arrange
an away team.
And I'll lead it.
You will lead it?
Yes.
Sir, we've had this
conversation 100 times.
And we will have it
again, number one.
I have been studying
the Iconians since I was
a cadet.
I have to be
the one to go.
The Enterprise
is yours.
For as long as she lasts.
O'BRIEN:
I've got a lock
on the energy source,
and, for the moment,
this baby's working.
That could change
in an instant.
PICARD:
We are aware of the risks.
Energize.
Transport complete.
Stay sharp,
Mr. O'Brien.
I want to be able
to pull them out of there
at a moment's notice.
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir.
Commander,
Romulan vessel.
RIKER:
Open hailing
frequencies.
They're arming
photon torpedoes.
Shields up.
Go to red alert.
Sir, the shields aren't
responding.
They're preparing
to fire photon torpedoes.
Mr. Crusher,
I need those shields.
I'm trying, sir.
They're firing.
What happened?
Instead of firing,
they suddenly disarmed
and cancelled.
Fate.
Protects fools,
little children,
and ships named
Enterprise.
Lock phasers on the Romulans
and hold your fire.
Sir, the shields
are back up.
Impeccable timing.
Sir, the shields
are back down.
Phaser banks are down.
Shields are back up.
In another time and place,
this could be funny.
Status of torpedo banks?
They're down, too.
If it should become
necessary to fight,
could you arrange to find me
some rocks to throw at them?
Sir, the Romulan torpedoes are
continuing to arm and disarm.
Perhaps its attempt to fire
was unintentional.
Open hailing frequencies.
Open.
Romulan vessel,
this is Commander William Riker,
first officer
of the USS Enterprise.
Why did you attempt
to fire on us?
This is Subcommander Taris
of the Haakona.
Why have you penetrated deeper
into the neutral zone?
Why are you still here?
I have claimed this planet
for the Romulan Empire.
This is
the Neutral Zone.
No one can claim anything.
You will withdraw,
or I will be forced to destroy
your ship and your away team.
What the hell?
This is your final warning.
I will not...
Having a little trouble
with your systems, Commander?
Maybe we should consider
postponing the war.
Until we solve our
more immediate problem.
You're stalling
for time.
Sir, another probe
launched for the planet.
Heading toward
the Romulans.
Have we got
our phasers back?
No, sir.
Taris, if you have
phaser capability,
prepare to
use them now.
What?
Destroy that probe.
Not even a thank you.
Subcommander Taris is
deeply frustrated,
probably because her ship is
as crippled as the Enterprise.
Why would the Romulans be
experiencing problems?
They weren't probed.
They must have tapped
into the Yamato log.
Taris got a whole lot more
than she bargained for.
RIKER:
Maintain red alert
and try to keep
those shields up in case
Taris decides to act
on her threat.
Commander.
What about the away team?
With the shields up,
we can't beam them back.
Captain's log,
supplemental.
While there is little left
on the surface of Iconia,
we have found what
appears to be a control center
which seems to have
remained intact.
WORF:
Come in, Enterprise.
Still no response, sir.
Keep trying them.
Communications are
bound to be erratic.
I would not like
to become
a permanent resident
of this planet.
Nor would I,
Mr. Worf.
Scanners show no other
life-forms on the planet, sir.
I would not expect any.
Judging from the severity
of the bombardment,
I doubt
any Iconians survived.
Well...
Mr. Data, let's see what sense
we can make of this.
Aye, sir.
This is very reminiscent
of Dinasian.
Yes, sir.
There are also similarities
to Dewan and Iccobar.
Is it possible they
could be branches
of the same language family,
beginning with Iconian?
It is, sir.
Run a comparison
using basic simple words
from Dinasian, Dewan,
and Iccobar.
Let's see if we can reconstruct
a common root language.
Accessing, sir.
You're jumpy.
The tension on the ship
is very high.
What's your
recommendation?
Give everyone
something to do,
somewhere to focus
their attention.
All right.
Let's consider
evacuation.
To the planet?
I know it's probably impossible
with Taris sitting out there...
but it would give
everyone something to do.
You go and organize it.
But you might need me
if you have to negotiate
with Taris again.
I'll manage.
Right now,
they're more important.
DATA:
Captain.
Your original hypothesis
is correct.
Iconian is the parent tongue
of a language family
which consists of Iccobar,
Dewan, and Dinasian.
I've constructed a basic
working understanding
through a comparison
of common root words
such as mother, father,
child, home, tribe,
food, life, death,
yours, ours, mine...
Data, Data, Data.
You do understand, sir,
that my interpretation
of the symbols
will not be exact?
Yes, let's
get on with it.
This would appear to be
manual override.
That was not
Demons of air
and darkness, indeed.
What is that?
A gateway.
These scenes could be
holographic images.
PICARD:
Be careful.
Data!
That was
very foolish.
But we have established
that this is not a holograph.
If I step through
and investigate,
we could determine whether
this is truly a gateway.
No, Data. You might not
be able to get back,
and I can't
risk losing you.
If it is not illusion,
this gate would seem to take us
beyond the confines
of this planet.
Is this how
the Iconians traveled?
Crossing light-years
as easily as
we would cross a room?
Those places
could be on worlds
in distant corners
of the galaxy.
I think the Iconians might
have outfoxed their enemies.
Maybe they didn't all die
in the bombardment.
Some of them could have
passed through this.
This is what
Varley feared.
he died for.
Sir?
The Romulans could use
this technology
as a weapon.
Like the Iconians did.
No, I disagree.
Captain, there is
nothing in this room
to indicate it was used
as a military command center.
Perhaps
a transporter room.
But the probe was
hostile.
We can't make
that assumption.
The effect on the Yamato
was devastating.
But what if it was
by accident, not design?
What I'm going to say
may sound unscientific,
but standing on this soil,
breathing in this air,
my instincts tell me that
we may have got them wrong.
But we do know
the Iconians were conquerors.
But that knowledge
was passed down
by the descendants of those
who attacked this world.
The victors invariably
write the history
to their own
advantage.
There is an unfortunate
tendency in many cultures
to fear what they
do not understand.
It's possible
that their enemies,
confronted by
this technology,
were driven to attack
the Iconians out of fear.
Sir.
Was that really
the Enterprise?
I believe that
it was.
Gentlemen,
we have a way home.
Captain, there's a vast
underground power source
which is controlled
by this console.
I believe my triggering
of the gateway
has caused a dramatic
upsurge in the power level.
Ah, I have access.
( high-pitched tone )
PICARD:
Data, can you hear me?
Data, respond.
Captain...
Are you all right?
No... I am damaged.
How bad is it?
The Iconian program
is attempting to rewrite
my software.
Physical
manifestations--
blindness, motor con...
Sir.
Without him,
we have no hope
of deciphering
the program.
Captain,
the Enterprise again.
How long is
the interval?
About four minutes,
if the cycle holds.
The next time
the Enterprise appears,
go through it
with Data.
Geordi will be able
to learn from him,
maybe help him.
Sir, we have not
yet established
that that is
truly a gateway.
This will be
the test.
Aye, sir.
Destroy the tricorder.
Sir, it contains
everything
we've discovered
up to this point.
And that is precisely
why it must be destroyed.
PICARD:
How long?
About three minutes.
I'm running out of time.
We all are.
Data.
Data...
I have to destroy this.
This control room
and its technology
must not be allowed to fall
into Romulan hands.
DATA:
I understand, sir.
How?
How do I do it?
How do I destroy
everything?
The control room,
the probes, all of it?
The power source, sir.
I detonate it?
But how?
How do I do that?
The probes, sir.
The probes?
The probes.
Launch?
I launch the probes?
But why?
What good will that do?
The doors, sir.
Doors?
Perhaps the probes are
in a launch bay.
And if the doors
are closed,
then the backwash from
the rockets will spill
into the power grids,
and there will be an overload.
Yes, sir.
But the doors will
open automatically
when the launch begins.
And I will override.
Correct, sir.
Which control keys--
damn.
Of course,
you can't see.
Help.
Worf, help him up.
Describe, please.
I'm standing directly
in front of the gate.
To my left, there is
a small, triangular screen.
Right... one... meter.
Right.
Now, to my right is
a larger, triangular screen.
To the top is solid amber,
to the left, red.
DATA:
Correct.
Key blue, amber,
amber, red.
That's the launch sequence?
How do I override
the doors?
Blue, blue, blue.
I hope that's not
a stutter.
I don't know how long
a delay there will be
between the launch
and the detonation.
I will hold keying
the launch sequence
until you're through
the gate.
How long until
the Enterprise reappears?
Almost time.
Captain,
you will be killed.
I'll go through
the gate.
But where will
you end up?
Very shortly, anywhere will be
preferable to this room.
Mr. Worf,
I am depending on you.
You must get Data back
to the Enterprise.
He may be
their only hope.
Aye, sir.
CREWMEMBER:
Commander, look!
Worf! What happened?
Where's the captain?
We must take Data
to engineering.
Hopefully,
the captain will follow.
I don't know
how to help him.
But comparing
recorded norms for Data
to these current
readings, it's clear
that all his functions
are just going crazy.
If we had an expert,
a maddox, somebody, I...
( monitor beeping goes flat )
He's gone.
ICONIAN COMPUTER:
Kandar qui,
kandar pro,
kandar kija,
kandar sis,
kandar...
Data!
What the hell?
I am accessing.
The self-correcting
mechanism.
DATA:
Captain? Captain!
Its constantly kicking in
to make minute adjustments
in the positronic brain.
I am on the Enterprise.
How did I get here?
He cleared the Iconian program
from his system-- how?
Iconia...
I was on Iconia,
now I am on
the Enterprise.
Geordi, this is
critical-- how?!
Okay, give me
a second to think.
There was an incompatible
program running through
Data's system,
so the mechanism
started searching for
a way to keep him alive.
The solution...
the solution was
a shutdown
and a total wipe
of all affected memory.
Query.
What have I forgotten?
Can you do the same thing
with the Enterprise?
I don't see why not.
But it will have to be
a complete shutdown--
we turn her off
and affect a wipe
of the Yamato log
including every subsequent event
since we downloaded it.
I'll then be able to
reload all the ship's programs
from the protected archives
in the main core.
Geordi,
if we shut down,
that means we're going to be
bringing down the shields,
and we're hanging nose to nose
with a Romulan battle cruiser.
Hey, Commander,
whether it's Romulan phasers
or our own warp engines,
we're just as dead.
Make it so.
May I help?
Kandar nien,
kandar cobar,
kandar konyen...
All systems functioning.
Lock onto the captain
and bring him back.
Scanning, sir.
Got him.
Kandar jet,
kandar se,
kandar tor,
kandar eir,
kandar... kandar...
plo, kandar mota...
ROMULAN COMPUTER:
Setha-tri par trukatha.
Setha-tri
par trukatha.
Setha-tri par...
I've lost him.
Damn it!
Got him, sir.
He's on the Romulan ship.
How the h...?
Setha-tri
par dreka...
Go to your stations.
Setha-tri
par ruloko...
Setha-tri par riktu...
Setha-tri
par rallari...
You did this.
You sabotaged
my ship.
Oh, no.
I cannot deactivate
the auto-destruct.
But at least
I have the satisfaction
that you will die
with us.
Not I think today,
commander.
Setha-tri par...
Setha-tri
par rawltair...
Bridge, Picard.
Yes, Captain?
Take us out of here.
The Romulan vessel is
set to auto-destruct,
and they can't deactivate.
Wait, sir, open
hailing frequencies.
Open, sir.
Commander Taris,
prepare to receive
a transmission
from our chief engineer,
he'll instruct you
how to purge
your system.
TARIS:
Agreed, Enterprise.
Standing by.
Commander,
your transmission has been
received
and acknowledged.
Now, Mr. Data,
warp speed please.
Just in case
Taris's engineer
is not as efficient
as our Mr. La Forge.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
Well, Number One,
I can see why you want to keep
the away missions to yourself.
That's where
the excitement is.
So, what's been
happening here?
Same old routine,
I suppose?