PICARD:
Captain's log,
Stardate 42625.4.
We are entering orbit
around the eighth planet
in this previously unmapped
Theta 116 solar system.
We diverted from our
scheduled course
when a passing Klingon cruiser
reported discovering
pieces of a strange vessel
in the upper atmosphere
of this planet.
We have come to investigate.
Nasty.
Nitrogen, methane,
liquid neon.
Surface temperature,
-291 degrees Celsius.
Winds up to 312 meters
per second.
Not exactly a
vacation planet, huh?
Mm-mm, not unless you
like ammonia tornados.
But I have found
indications of debris
in an elliptical orbit.
RIKER:
You keep me informed.
The sooner we find out what
the Klingons think they saw,
the sooner we can get
the hell out of here.
Sounds good to me.
( shivers )
Nasty.
( door chimes )
Come.
Fermat's last theorem.
You're familiar
with it?
Vaguely.
I spent too many
math classes
daydreaming about
being on a starship.
Mmm.
When Pierre de Fermat died,
they found this equation
scrawled in the margin
of his notes--
"X to the nth plus Y to
the nth equals Z to the nth
where N is greater
than two,"
which he said had no
solution in whole numbers.
But, he also added this
phrase, "remarkable proof."
Yeah, that's starting
to come back to me.
There was no proof included.
Mm-hmm, and for
800 years,
people have been
trying to solve it.
Including you.
I find it stimulating.
Also, it puts things
in perspective.
In our arrogance,
we feel we are so advanced.
And yet, we cannot
unravel a simple knot
tied by a part-time
French mathematician
working alone
without a computer.
Captain, we've detected some
sort of debris in loose orbit.
Can you identify it?
No, sir.
I suggest we beam a section
aboard for analysis.
Make it so, Number One.
We've locked onto something
with markings on it.
What sort
of markings?
Uncertain.
Energize.
We've got ourselves
a little puzzle, Number One.
Yes, sir,
I guess we have.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Analysis bears out
that the object
was definitely
terrestrial in origin
dated mid-21st century.
No, no.
No Earth ship of that time
could have traveled
out this far.
Nevertheless, that is
what our tests indicate.
And the markings we
discovered are consistent
with this hypothesis.
Any indication
of what destroyed it, Data?
That is even
more significant
than the object itself,
Counselor.
On several of
its surfaces,
the molecules seem to
have disintegrated.
Disintegrated how?
Almost as if they were hit
by a weapon from our time.
Curiouser
and curiouser.
WESLEY:
Captain, we've detected
a large structure
on the planet.
WESLEY:
It's a building of some sort,
situated on a plane
of frozen methane
smack in the middle of a
tremendous storm belt.
I don't believe this.
That structure is surrounded
with breathable air.
Is there any connection
between that structure
and the ship fragment
that we found?
Unknown, sir.
Suggestions?
Well just one, sir-- we can go
down there and have a look.
Breathable air.
No life forms that
might be dangerous.
I think we could risk
a minimal away team,
Number One.
Give me a moment, gents,
we're dealing with
an extremely
narrow access point.
Phasers on stun.
Ready when you are.
I believe we've got it now.
You have a green light,
Commander.
Energize.
Those ammonia storms are less
than a kilometer away.
Yet they do not appear to
penetrate this breathable zone.
It's like the eye
of a hurricane.
Commander, what is that?
A door.
The structure must be here,
yet we cannot see it.
Enterprise,
this is Commander Riker.
As your readout shows,
this is an unusual place.
Completely calm, no sound,
no movement,
yet a few hundred meters away,
a storm is raging.
PICARD: Any information
about the structure?
Yes, sir, there's an
antique revolving door.
It could be an entrance.
Revolving door?
Number One,
proceed with caution.
RIKER:
Yes, sir.
Well, this is what
we came here for.
Captain, we're entering.
( conversational chatter
and slot machines ringing )
Enterprise to away team,
come in.
We're receiving no signal
at all from them, sir.
Transporter room,
lock on to the landing party,
beam them up.
We've got nothing
to lock on to, sir.
Riker to Enterprise.
We've entered
the structure.
Riker to Enterprise,
come in.
Come in, Enterprise.
When they went through
that antique doorway,
their signal just
disappeared, sir.
What's causing
the interference?
Unknown.
They're receiving us?
No.
We're going to have to
recalibrate all the frequencies
to find one that'll work.
Then do it.
Sir, without communication,
we should beam up immediately.
We're here.
There's no danger.
We'll look around,
then leave.
Checking in, gentlemen?
You'll have to go
to the front desk.
Very good.
We'll start with that.
( clears throat )
Welcome, gentlemen.
Have a nice trip?
Do you know us?
We've been expecting you.
A trio of
foreign gentlemen.
Yes, we're from the United
Federation of Planets.
Of course you are.
Welcome to the Hotel Royale.
Excuse me.
Did Rita call?
I'm busy.
You're busy?
This is my life
I'm talking about here.
Now, did Rita call
or not?
No, and for your own good,
you better quit
thinking about Rita.
I'm not afraid
of Mickey D.
Then you're a fool.
Anybody with any sense
is afraid of Mickey D.
If Rita calls,
you let me know.
Kid's just asking
for trouble.
Rita's too much
for him to handle,
and Mickey D's gonna plant
his face in the pavement.
Now, here are your room keys.
And some complimentary
casino chips.
Enjoy.
What is this place?
How did a being
like you get here?
Well, this is the Royale,
of course.
And my personal life is really
none of your business,
thank you.
What he means is
what planet is this?
I beg your pardon?
This planet--
what do you call it?
Earth.
What do you call it?
We call it Theta Eight.
How charming.
Commander?
Yes, Data?
None of these people
are emitting life signs.
You mean,
they're not alive?
Then what are they?
( overlapping chatter )
These beings--
are they machines,
or mere illusions
designed to deceive us?
Not illusion, Lieutenant.
They do exist.
But they do not register
as either man or machine.
Take this creature,
for example.
He does not exhibit
any DNA structure.
Excuse me, son.
Look who's talking.
Man, you sound just like
my ex-wife.
All right.
Time to get down
to "bidness."
What sort of "bidness"
do you suppose he is
getting down to?
Status report.
We're attempting to employ
alternate encoding schemes.
There could be hundreds
of possible combinations.
Is there an intelligence
causing this interference?
Mmm.
No, that's impossible
to tell, Captain.
It's unlike Commander Riker
not to follow procedure.
When he lost contact
with the Enterprise
he should have
returned immediately
to the beam-down
coordinates.
I don't feel he's
in any danger.
In fact, if I could choose
one word to assess his mood,
it would be amused.
"Amused?"
( sighs )
What about some chips there,
mister?
Yessiree!
( laughing )
Oh.
You're new around
here, aren't you?
Yes, sir.
Then sit down.
I'm gonna teach you how
this game is played, boy.
( laughing )
Go ahead, ante up.
( inhales deeply )
I'll be.
He wants you
to cut the cards.
Ah!
Is this poker?
No, no. Blackjack.
Blackjack.
Accessing.
Ah, also known as "21."
A number which defines
the object of the game.
Picture cards
are worth ten,
aces, one or 11,
all other cards,
face value.
Boy, you're right.
You are right.
( whistles )
MAN:
Pretty smooth.
Run 'em, boy.
Make 'em nice, 'cause ain't
no bread in the house.
21, 21, 21.
Don't look at
your hand, honey.
That gal has got to win.
Now, honey, you got 15 and
the dealer's showing ten.
Do I hit, Texas,
or do I stand?
If you gotta win,
you gotta hit.
Hit me.
Ooh.
TEXAS: Aw.
Damn!
Shoot.
Hit me.
Twenty-one, and a winner.
Yessiree!
Hit me.
Another, please.
Don't you think
you've had about enough?
If the objective of the game
is to approach a total
of 21 points,
I will definitely
need another card.
Yeah.
Boy, you have got the brass.
Do you know the what odds are
on a five-card Charlie?
Hell, you're just
throwing your money away.
Hit me.
TEXAS:
How'd you...
WOMAN:
Ooh!
TEXAS:
Well, shut my mouth.
Hey, you're not one of them
card-counting fellows, are you?
The number of the cards
and their values
remain quite constant.
What would be the purpose
in counting them?
Yeah.
RIKER:
You having fun, Data?
Fun, sir?
While there is a certain
amount of enjoyment involved,
I am mainly conducting
research in--
Save it.
We're getting out of here.
Understood, sir.
TEXAS:
Guys are holding up the game.
Our apologies, sir.
I'll watch your chips.
Oh, thank you, sir.
Hey...
The hat.
Sorry, sir.
Deal 'em up.
Progress?
We've accessed the range of
encoding scheme alternates.
The difficulty's in
the frequency range.
And the interference
is highly variable.
See, the problem may be
with the envelope
covering the structure.
There are hydrogen-carbon
helix patterns throughout.
Any transmissions
are simply scattered
and refracted at random.
No wonder you can't
get through.
Exactly.
PICARD: Those are some
fairly aggressive
computations, Lieutenant.
I'm comparing the
molecular integrity
of that bubble against
our phasers.
Is penetration possible?
I don't know just yet,
it may be an option.
I'd like to run this test.
Make it so.
Let's try that again.
Let's find another way
out of here.
Excuse me.
Aside from the main door,
is there another exit
I might use?
( slot machine ringing )
( gasps )
Ooh!
Excuse...
Excuse me...
Say, I was wondering if
you could tell me...
( grunts )
It's a good deal of
structural integrity, Worf.
Permission to use
phaser, sir.
Granted.
Sir, I can find
no other exits.
I believe
we are trapped here.
Captain's log, supplemental.
We remain in orbit
around Theta Eight,
still out of contact
with the away team.
We're almost there, Captain.
We'll be able to attempt
contact in a few minutes.
Captain, the situation
down there has changed.
In what way?
Commander Riker has
become tense...
closed in.
He's feeling trapped.
Phasers are totally
ineffective on all surfaces.
Sir, our options
appear quite limited.
We don't have any.
If we're going to get
out of here, we're going to
have to do it on our own.
I'm gonna get some answers
out of that desk clerk.
Are you crazy?
Wrong.
I'm finally getting
some smarts.
You think you're gonna scare
Mickey D with that gun?
I'm gonna make him
leave Rita alone.
Kid, she's a big girl.
And she's
Mickey D's girl.
Not anymore.
Not after tonight.
Look kid, I like you.
I don't wanna
see you get hurt,
especially over
some dame.
Don't call her that.
You'll see.
You'll see how tough
Mickey D is.
He's nothing.
( deep sigh )
I want some answers.
I'm sure the concierge
will be happy--
We would like to
get out of here now.
The Royale's exits
are clearly marked.
That's not good enough.
If you have a complaint
about the service
you've received
during your stay here,
you can always take it up
with the manager.
Fine, I'd like to
see him immediately.
I'm afraid the manager
is very busy.
PICARD:
Riker, can you read me?
Yes.
There's a good deal of
interference, Captain,
but you are getting through.
Number One, why haven't
you left that building?
We tried, sir, it seems
like we're trapped in here.
We're in no immediate danger,
but I am concerned.
Something about your location is
interfering with communication.
We are working on the problem.
RIKER:
Standing by, sir.
Captain, these frequencies
are unstable.
Then find others.
Yes, sir.
What is going on
down there?
DATA:
Commander?
I am picking up
something most unusual
in another section
of this structure.
It appears to be human DNA.
Where?
31.9 meters above
and to the right of us.
Perhaps those turbolifts
could take us there.
Seems to be
malfunctioning.
( elevator dings )
The reading I received is
from behind this door, sir.
My reading is
intensifying, sir.
RIKER:
Are you getting any life signs?
None, sir.
Definitely human.
Male.
Looks like the poor devil
died in his sleep.
What a terrible
way to die.
He has been dead for
283 years, sir.
The lack of any
advanced decomposition
is due to the sterile
environment.
Why would anyone
go to all this trouble?
It's just window dressing
for a dead man.
WORF:
Commander.
Is this significant, sir?
American.
DATA:
52 stars, sir.
Places it between
2033 and 2079 A.D.
Correlates with the
debris we found.
Colonel S. Richey.
Rest in peace,
Colonel.
Picard to Riker.
Finally.
Riker. Go ahead.
You're coming through
clearly now.
What's your situation?
Well, this structure was
apparently made to resemble
20th century Earth.
All attempts to exit
have failed.
PICARD: We haven't found a way
to transport you back yet.
I assumed as much, sir.
We've also located the
remains of a human.
Request
identity scan.
Colonel Richey,
American,
first initial, "S."
Roughly the same
time period.
Do it.
Commander,
some curiosities.
Books.
A novel-- Hotel Royale.
Summarize, please.
Information retrieved,
Captain.
Number One?
RIKER:
Go ahead, Captain.
We have the information
you requested.
Colonel Stephen Richey
was the commanding officer
of the explorer ship
Charybdis,
which had a terrestrial
launch date of July 23, 2037.
It was the third
manned attempt
to travel beyond the confines
of Earth's solar system.
Its telemetry failed,
it was never heard from again.
Do you believe that
you've discovered
the remains of
Colonel Richey?
Yes. And Captain,
we found something else.
A novel by Todd Matthews
entitled Hotel Royale,
which is the name
of this structure.
Data.
Captain, this is the story of
a group of compulsive gamblers
caught up in a web of crime,
corruption and deceit.
It is told by
nefarious lothario, Mickey D,
who appears only at the
climax of the story,
to carry out the
cold-blooded murder
of the hotel bellboy.
There is also a subplot
about an older man
conspiring with
a younger woman
to murder her husband.
She is squandering
her inheritance--
Captain, this novel and
everything Data just described
seems to be exactly what's
happening at this hotel.
Extraordinary.
RIKER: There's also
one other thing.
A diary with only one entry,
obviously made
by Colonel Richey.
PICARD: Can you read it?
Yes.
"I write this in the hope
"that it will someday
be read by human eyes.
"I can only surmise
at this point,
"but apparently our exploratory
shuttle was contaminated
"by an alien life-form
"which infected and killed
all personnel except myself.
"I awakened to find myself
here in the Royale Hotel
"precisely as described in
the novel I found in my room.
"And for the last 38 years
I have survived here.
"I have come to understand
that the alien contaminators
"created this place for me
out of some sense of guilt,
"presuming that the novel
we had on board the shuttle
"about the Hotel Royale
"was in fact a guide to
our preferred lifestyle
"and social habits.
"Obviously, they thought this
was the world from which I came.
"I hold no malice
toward my benefactors.
"They could not possibly
know the hell
"that they have
put me through.
"For it was such
a badly written book
"filled with endless cliche
and shallow characters.
I shall welcome death
when it comes."
I understand,
Number One.
Now, we know why
all that is there,
why can't you get out?
Number One.
RIKER: Yes, sir.
Lieutenant La Forge
has a thought.
He believes we can phaser
a slice in the field
surrounding the structure.
That means the atmosphere of the
planet would instantly rush in.
Our projected survival would
be approximately 12 seconds.
Correct.
The cryogenic process
would be nearly
instantaneous.
RIKER: But I assume
you could revive us?
Yes, in theory.
PICARD:
You must understand, Number One.
We'll wait here for
months if necessary.
We're just
considering options.
RIKER:
If you're trying to motivate us
to find our own
way out of here,
you've succeeded, Captain.
( telephone ringing )
Yes?
There is a female voice
asking if we want room service.
I believe she is asking if
we want the room cleaned.
Tell her no.
No.
What did she say?
She said the kitchen
will be open 24 hours
if we change our minds.
We'll go to explore
the rest of the hotel.
We'll keep a com line open.
You two, go down
to the lobby and see if there's
anything that we missed.
You talk to the guests,
try to find out
who or what they are.
I'll check out the
rest of the floors.
Computer, locate and display
the text of the novel
entitled Hotel Royale,
by Todd Matthews.
COMPUTER:
Accessing.
If the cause of the
difficulties is in the novel,
we may find the solution
within its pages.
Ah.
"It was a dark and
stormy night..."
( sighs )
That's not a promising
beginning.
It may get better.
I suggest we separate and
blend in with these beings.
Casual queries offered
inconspicuously
might prove fruitful.
( overlapping chatter )
WOMAN:
I need a four. Give me a four.
Damn!
Oh, shoot!
How much do I
have left here?
Honey, now, you know
it's bad luck
to count your
chips at the table.
Yeah?
Excuse me, sir.
Might I inquire,
where are you from?
Lubbock, Texas.
And how did
you get here?
To Vegas?
Drove my car.
I got a '91 Caddy with
only 80,000 miles on it.
Where is your
automobile now?
Out front, I suppose.
What the hell difference
does it make?
Could you take me there?
WOMAN:
Hit me.
I'm losing my shirt.
TEXAS: Son, why would
I want to do that?
Can't you see I'm trying
to help this little lady?
I believe you are trapped
inside the Royale,
just as I am.
Sure does seem that way when
you're losing, don't it?
We're just trying to
turn this lady wagon around
and win back some
lost change.
Otherwise, she's in
a desperate situation
and she's got nowhere to turn.
Well...
almost nowhere.
I stay, right?
I wouldn't.
The odds favor
standing pat.
What do I do?
Do you want a card or not?
Hit me.
Oh, too many.
Oh...
I've almost lost it all.
What am I gonna do?
There, there, there...
What did you find?
Nothing.
ASSISTANT MANAGER:
Kid, Rita just called.
She did?
What did she say?
It was kinda hard
to tell, she was crying.
Crying?
Damn!
Mickey D thinks he can treat
people any way he wants.
Well, that's all over now.
You were told.
It's not for you
to make the call.
It's for Rita.
She sent me to tell you.
Okay, boys, look,
we can't afford
to have any trouble in here.
Why don't you just
take this outside?
Yeah.
I like that.
Come on, baggage man.
Let's you and me
take it outside.
BELLBOY: When I was a kid,
I used to look up to you guys.
The suit,
the fancy shoes.
I really thought that
made you somebody.
But you're nobody.
( Picard lowers volume )
I don't believe
this dialogue.
Did humans really
talk like that?
Not in real life.
Remember, everything that's
going on down there
is taken from what
Colonel Richey calls
a second-rate novel.
BELLBOY: ...Rita, she could
do something with her life.
With your permission, sir.
MICKEY D:
She's somebody, she's my girl.
BELLBOY:
You got her on the stuff.
That's the only reason
she stays with you.
Because you
feed her sickness.
You gotta let me help her.
Well, why don't we just go
outside and talk about it?
Just watch yourself.
Don't worry.
It's all part
of the novel.
Don't interfere.
( screams )
You shoulda listened
to me, kid.
No woman's
worth dying for.
Killing for, not dying for.
Riker to Enterprise.
Yes, Number One.
RIKER: A bizarre incident
just took place.
The shoot-out between
the bellboy and Mickey D.
Yes, and Mickey D just
walked out the door.
How did he do that?
It's on page 244.
In the novel, right.
How does it end?
A bad love affair ends
in a bloody shoot-out.
The hotel gets bought out,
and life goes on...
such as it is.
The hotel gets bought?
By whom?
It isn't specific.
Simply refers to
"foreign investors."
Sale price: 12.5 million
United States dollars.
They return home, leaving the
assistant manager in charge.
Captain, that's how
we're getting out.
We're buying this place.
It is all a question
of probabilities.
Quite simple, really,
if one bets with any
sequential consistency.
Elaborate.
The combinations
totalling seven or 11
have considerable value when
achieved on the primary attempt.
With eight variations possible
to create those totals,
the likelihood
of those totals occurring
is not significant, however--
Okay, okay, can you do it?
I believe so, sir.
Eight's the point.
Eighter from Decatur.
Can I see no eyes?
Do it, do it.
Oh, snake eyes.
Single digits on each cube
are not at all desirable.
You're almost broke.
Relax, honey.
It's only money.
Yeah, but if you
lose it all,
I won't even have
a place to sleep.
Don't you worry your
little head, honey.
I'd never let that happen.
Go, baby.
Let's go.
Here they come.
Here they come, babe.
CROUPIER: Seven, out.
TEXAS: Ah, I'm out.
Your turn, slick.
Go to work.
Maybe this turkey will
bring us some luck.
Six.
Six is your number.
Hell, my blind grandma
can make a six, boy.
Come on, roll 'em.
I thought seven
and 11 had value.
Actually, six is a valid point.
Of course, now, the objective
is to roll
a duplicate six
before hitting seven.
But the probability
of making a six
is no greater than
that of rolling a seven.
There is a certain degree of
random fortune involved.
I believe that is why
they call it gambling.
Yeah.
CROUPIER: Seven.
Seven away. Next shooter.
So much for
your new turkey.
Give slick another shot.
I got a feeling
about you, boy.
Commander, these cubes are
improperly balanced.
I believe their final
resting position would be--
Can you repair them?
I believe so.
I will make another attempt.
Baby needs a new pair
of shoes.
11! That a boy.
Do that a few more times,
we all gonna get well.
Whoo!
Seven, winner.
And another one!
( laughing )
Keep going, boy, we got 'em
hot now, let's go, let's go!
RIKER: Double 'em up.
Here we go.
Keep it rolling, boy,
keep it rolling.
TEXAS:
Seven, a winner!
Status, Number One?
We're having a nice
run of luck, Captain.
PICARD: Don't get out
of character, Commander.
Sir?
The foreign investors
in the book
are described
as flamboyantly generous.
Yes, sir.
I understand.
Whoo! Big seven.
Look at that!
Oh!
Tex, darling.
You're brilliant.
Yeah, and I'm
good-looking, too, huh?
( laughing )
Isn't that enough?
No, don't wanna
come up short.
You are keeping count?
Yes, sir.
12.3 million.
Perhaps I
will bet...
$700,000.
No, bet it all.
But sir, the sale price of this
edifice is 12.5 million.
We need some
spreading around money, Data.
Sir?
Bet it all.
Here you go.
A little something
for you, Ziggy.
A little something for
those cocktail waitresses.
Run this outside and give it
to the parking lot attendants.
You're very kind, sir.
Here you go, Vanessa.
A little something for you, too.
Thank you.
When the train comes in,
everybody rides.
Yeah, and I'm getting
off at this station.
After 18 passes,
air gets a little too thin
for this country boy.
I'm betting against
you fellows.
Are you nuts?
I do not believe that is
a prudent choice, sir.
Hey, that's what
horse racing's about.
Roll 'em, boy.
CROUPIER:
Seven. Seven a winner.
Whoo!
The man has the touch.
You knew you were gonna throw
that seven, didn't you?
You just let me
go down the tubes.
I tried to caution you, sir.
What was it?
I mean...
was it personal or-- or what?
Because I didn't
show you my car?
Now.
I wish to cash in, sir.
I'm afraid you've
broken the bank.
Just take 12.5 million, the
purchase price of this hotel.
Spread the rest around.
Whew.
You're the foreign investors.
That's right.
We just bought this place,
lock, stock and barrel.
Consider it a done deal.
I like you fellas.
You got style.
Let me buy
you guys a drink.
Just enjoy the game.
Don't let 'em change
the dice on you.
TEXAS:
You got it.
Phew.
Enterprise, this
is the away team.
We're clear of
the structure.
Three to beam up.
Time to come home now,
Number One.
Transporter room,
we have a fix on the away team.
Beam them up.
( chime )
Come.
Sir.
Welcome back, Number One.
Very strange experience.
Puzzling.
I still can't comprehend
how Colonel Richey's vessel
could've traveled
out that far.
Not on its own,
at any rate.
Perhaps they were
brought here
by whoever created that
make-believe world down there.
It's possible they didn't
know how fragile
the humans aboard
actually were.
Only one of them survived.
None of it
makes any sense.
Like Fermat's theorem, it's
a puzzle we may never solve.