( humming jazzy tune )
( door chime )
RIKER:
Come on in.
Excellent.
That's exactly
what I needed.
Ah, Mr. Worf.
And the good Doctor
bearing gifts?
Ale from Ennan VI.
Your omelets
deserve no less.
This is not
an efficient method
for the preparation
of sustenance.
Oh, you're right, Data.
The ship's computer
would be more efficient,
but it wouldn't allow
for the subtlety needed
for great cooking.
It would give you
all of the ingredients
in predetermined
measurements.
It wouldn't allow for
flair or individuality.
And, Data, as we both know,
flair is what marks
the difference
between artistry
and mere competence.
For much of the history
of mankind,
the breaking of bread
was a symbol of friendship
and community--
something we've gotten
away from in the 24th century.
Ah, you have a practiced
hand, Commander.
Yes, I have my father to thank.
Your father
liked to cook?
No, he hated it.
That's why he left
the chore to me.
It is my understanding
that in most human families,
the woman shares
in the cooking.
There were only
the two of us.
I never knew my mother.
She died
when I was very young.
Where did you get these eggs?
On our last stop.
At Starbase 73?
Yep.
What kind of eggs
did you say these were?
Owon.
For you, Data.
Something special.
Don't be afraid.
They won't bite you.
And for you,
Mr. Worf.
( coughs )
A cook is only as good
as his ingredients.
( groans )
Delicious.
PICARD:
Number One.
Go ahead.
I'd appreciate you joining me
on the bridge.
Right away, sir.
Number One, we've picked up
an automated signal
from a Federation
shuttlecraft.
From a shuttlecraft?
How is that possible?
I thought we were
the only manned
Federation vessel out here.
Apparently not.
What's a shuttlecraft
doing out this far?
Where's its mother ship?
WORF:
Sensors indicate
there is at least
one life-form aboard
the shuttle, sir-- humanoid.
Perhaps someone to answer
your questions, Number One.
Open hailing frequencies.
Communication
is not possible, sir.
The shuttle is without power.
Set course to intercept.
Estimate intercept
in three minutes.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42679.2.
While en route
to the Endicor system,
we have encountered
a Federation shuttlecraft
which seems to have appeared
out of nowhere.
There are no indications
of where it came from,
or how it got out here.
We are closing
on the shuttlecraft, sir.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
On screen.
Magnify.
Prepare to lock on
tractor beam.
Target vehicle.
We will be within tractor beam
range in two seconds.
Set automatic locking device.
Alert Shuttle Bay 2.
( warning Klaxon sounds )
DATA:
Shuttle Bay 2,
prepare for retrieval procedure.
Locking tractor beam.
Number One.
You're with me, Mr. Worf.
Dr. Pulaski, you are needed
in Shuttle Bay 2.
PULASKI:
I've been monitoring.
I'm on my way.
DATA:
Engage secondary tractor beam.
Well, that's a Federation
shuttlecraft, all right.
Yet, there are
no Federation bases
or vessels in this area.
"NCC-1701-D,
USS Enterprise,
Shuttlecraft 05."
"NCC-1701-D, USS Enterprise,
How is this possible?
Commander, come here!
Captain?
Yes, Number One?
Are you on the bridge?
Where else would I be?
Well, right now, I think you
should be in Shuttle Bay 2.
Why? What is it?
This, I think,
you should see for yourself.
Bring Commander Data.
Condition?
PULASKI:
The life signs
are very confusing.
His heartbeat is strong,
but the pulse is off.
Is he injured?
There's no signs
of trauma.
Why is he unconscious?
What happened to him?
I can't say.
The readings
of his brain waves
are very strange.
Strange?
What way?
Non-human?
Artificial?
No, neither.
They're just out of phase.
Can you revive him?
I wouldn't even
attempt it
until we get him
into Sick Bay.
Come on, let's
get him there.
Counselor?
I have never felt anything
quite like this before,
so it's difficult
to put into words.
That person is you.
No.
He is as much Jean-Luc Picard
as the person
I'm standing next to.
Beyond that, there is
very little I can be sure of.
I will have to wait
until he regains consciousness
before knowing more.
Data.
I need to know what's
on the shuttle's logs.
Aye, sir.
Captain, both primary
and reserve power
has been drained
from the shuttle.
I am going to have to connect
to the Enterprise in order
to activate the
shuttle's systems.
Geordi...
report to Shuttle Bay 2
immediately.
I'm on my way.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
Keep me informed.
Captain, have you seen this?
It looks like
the damage
caused by an anti-matter
explosion.
It must have been
just out of range
of the shuttlecraft.
Data, I need those logs.
Counselor.
We'll be on the bridge.
Lieutenant.
Resume course and speed.
Scanners at maximum range.
Maximum range.
There you go.
You should have power now.
Ooh, what happened?
The polarity is
not compatible.
That's not possible.
The connection's
idiot-proof.
The power requirements
of the shuttle
do not match those
of the Enterprise.
We will need a variable
phase inverter
to align the power
from the Enterprise
to the circuits
of the shuttle.
Data, what do you think
is going on here?
I don't mean
just with the shuttle.
I mean everything.
I do not have
enough information.
I'm just starting
a complete medical work-up.
His vital signs
are distorted.
Some of the indicators
are totally depressed.
Others are
fluctuating wildly.
I can't explain any of it.
But he is alive.
The restraints are
for his own protection.
Have you been able to determine
why he's still unconscious?
No, but I have been able
to rule out any head injury.
Wake him.
What happened?
Apparently, the normal stimulant
had the opposite effect.
I'll have to try something else.
All right, Data.
I think I've
got it now.
That ought to give
you something.
Making this
power adjustment
is very tricky.
By all rights,
this connection
should blow all the
shuttle's circuits.
Perhaps you had better
step out of the way.
All right.
But, remember,
you're not indestructible
yourself, you know.
Increase the power.
Powering up.
Adjust the inverter
two percent positive.
Two percent positive.
It was the right decision,
but it's having
the opposite effect.
Yes.
I don't understand.
I can't think of anything
that would cause the circuit
to change so radically.
Adjust the inverter
two percent negative.
Okay.
Two percent negative.
That's it.
It shouldn't work,
but it does.
Hey, Data...
take a look
at the Stardate.
42679.5.
Captain.
Go ahead.
Captain, we've been able
to reactivate the shuttle
and the on-board clock
indicates that the shuttle
is six hours in front of us.
Captain, do you read me?
If the shuttle is
from six hours into the future,
then so is
the other Captain Picard.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Part of the mystery
has been solved.
The reason there are two
number 05 shuttlecrafts
is because one of them
is from the future.
Six hours to be exact.
And so, presumably,
is the facsimile of me.
Try and wake him again.
No.
It's only a sedative.
I know what it is.
Don't sedate him.
Let him be.
Please.
Let him remain conscious.
I've never seen
anything like this.
Are you all right?
I'm fine, Doctor.
Save your ministrations
for your patient.
I want a staff meeting
in five minutes.
Doctor, I assume
you will want to remain here?
Yes, I will monitor
the conference from here.
Keep me informed.
Of any changes,
no matter how small.
Captain's log, supplemental.
I've been informed
that Mr. Data
has recovered the logs from
the duplicate shuttlecraft.
I am more than apprehensive
to play back a log
which will not be recorded
for several hours.
Captain, we've retrieved
all we're going to get
out of the shuttle logs,
including
the last visual records.
Everything before that
is just a jumble.
Show me.
The distortion is because
we had to use a phase inverter
to retrieve the logs.
The quality will improve...
slightly.
According to the shuttle log,
the Enterprise was destroyed
three hours,
19 minutes from now.
LA FORGE:
Captain...
we also have a portion
of the last log entry.
It's audio only.
Captain's Personal Log,
supplemental.
I have just witnessed
the total destruction
of the USS Enterprise
with a loss of all hands,
save one--
me.
All attempts to obtain
further information
from the shuttle have failed.
Well, at least now
we have something to go on.
LA FORGE:
I just don't understand
how you could have
ended up in a shuttlecraft
while the Enterprise
was being destroyed.
Nor I.
The last thing you would do
is leave the bridge
of the Enterprise
during an emergency.
Yes.
All right, let's
proceed on the premise
that what we have just seen
happened
and that, in less
than four hours from now,
the Enterprise will be destroyed
and, somehow,
although this is unfathomable,
I, and I alone, escape.
Discussion.
RIKER:
Our destination
is the Endicor system.
We're due to arrive
in three days.
The charts show nothing
of consequence,
certainly nothing
to threaten the Enterprise
between here and there.
Sensors indicated
no other vessels--
Federation or otherwise--
in this area.
Data?
I have nothing to offer.
There is not enough information
upon which to base
an hypothesis.
LA FORGE:
Well, the shuttle
apparently came
from somewhere up ahead.
So, rather than continuing
on this course,
maybe we should stop here
and let whatever it is
out there come to us.
RIKER:
We may already
be too late.
What are you saying?
That stopping,
turning right or left,
even reversing our course
would be pointless?
When we brought the shuttle
and the other Picard onboard,
we committed
to a sequence of events
which may be unalterable.
PICARD:
Yes, this is not some...
rock on the trail
which once seen
can easily be avoided.
This is much
more complex.
There is the theory
of the Mobius--
a twist in the fabric of space
where time becomes a loop
from which there
is no escape.
So, when we reach that point,
whatever happened
will happen again--
the Enterprise will be
destroyed,
the other Picard will be
sent back to meet with us,
and we do it all over again.
Sounds like someone's idea
of hell to me.
Well, I know this much--
we can't avoid the future.
Agreed.
So let's continue on course.
Somewhere out there
something will happen.
A decision will be made
during the course
of which
I will be separated
from the Enterprise.
At the time,
the decision will seem
to be correct,
but it won't be.
We have to anticipate
and not make...
not make the same mistake once.
Something is
waiting for us
out there.
Let's try and determine what
it is as quickly as possible.
Doctor?
I'm just beginning
to realize
how much of the body
is held together by its
own internal clock.
He was thrown out of time,
which caused his body's systems
to change their rhythms.
Now slowly, as we get closer
to the time that he left,
his internal body clock
is realigning.
Are you saying
that when our time intersects
with the time he left--
in that instant, he will
function normally, and...
and there will be two of us?
Right now, that is my guess.
Doctor, I don't think
that's possible.
I'm able to feel much more
from him now, Captain.
His emotions are still
a jumble, but...
Counselor?
He desperately wants
to leave this ship.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We continue
on course to Endicor.
We are now
less than two hours away
from our rendezvous
with ourselves.
Worf.
Maximum scan, sir.
Nothing unusual
to report.
If this timetable
is correct,
we could get an indication
of something very soon.
PULASKI:
Bridge, this is Sick Bay.
Yes, Doctor.
Captain, my patient
is more coherent.
I'm on my way.
You have the bridge,
Number One.
How is he?
His vital signs
are more normal, which is
to say, more like ours.
He is calmer.
He's aware of me.
Perhaps, in
some fashion.
But he knows where he is,
who's here with him?
I doubt it.
What went wrong?
You know, don't you?
What did you do?
What happened?
Why did you leave the ship?
Don't turn away!
Look at me!
Picard, look at me.
Captain, he doesn't
understand you.
He knows I'm here.
Yes, but in a nightmare
of disjointed images
and half-heard voices.
He's in another dimension
looking at us
across a great chasm
and he's feeling remorse
at what he witnessed.
He's afraid.
What is he afraid of?
Damn you.
Help me.
Why did you
leave the ship?
It's no use, Captain.
He can't answer you.
When we get closer to his time,
he may be able to.
You're still
convinced he's me?
Yes, but you're
not convinced.
Not in the slightest.
Except for his features,
there is nothing about him
that I find familiar.
Counselor, I want you
to stay with him.
He'll be able to
communicate with you
before anyone else.
I don't know how long anyone
could take this kind
of anxiety state.
There has to be
a breaking point.
I think he's handling it
very well.
He has a lot of anger.
Yes, because of what he
represents.
And what is that?
Doubt.
He's afraid
that seeing him here
and knowing what happened
to the Enterprise
will make him timid,
or worse, make him hesitate.
Part of my job is
to anticipate problems.
My duty is
to the Captain
but first to the ship
and its crew.
Doctor,
the Captain is quite capable
of making command decisions.
Yes, for now,
but this situation has put him
under extreme pressure
of a unique
and very personal kind.
We both know
that pressure
will only increase.
You said yourself
that he already has doubt.
Which is understandable
and healthy.
And could be
potentially paralyzing.
Now, if we begin to see signs
that he's acting
in an irrational manner,
I have the authority
and the duty to relieve him.
I don't think
that will be necessary.
I hope you're right.
What force
or phenomenon
could cause the shuttle
to be thrown back in time?
None that we've
encountered.
In theory, accelerating
beyond warp ten.
Using the gravitational
pull of a star
to slingshot back in time?
Is that what happened here?
The shuttle doesn't have
warp capability.
No.
So, some external
force was needed.
We've never encountered
a natural force that powerful.
Why only six hours?
Why not a day or a year?
Are you saying that there was
some conscious mind
at work here?
There's no evidence
either way.
The Traveler moved through time
using the power of his mind.
I don't think
that's the case here.
No.
And Manheim's experiments
with gravity and time
were rudimentary
and uncontrollable.
Captain, I think
this is one instance
where you should suppress
your natural tendencies.
Oh, really?
One of your
strengths
is your ability to evaluate
the dynamics of a situation
and then take a definitive,
preemptive step-- take charge.
Now, you're
frustrated
because you not only
can't see the solution, you
can't even define the problem.
Hmm.
Go on.
What we're facing is neither
a person nor a place...
at least not yet.
It's time.
You're saying I should just
sit down, shut up and wait.
Well, I wouldn't have
put it exactly like that.
Not something I do easily.
Your Persian flaw.
Yes, perhaps it is.
WORF:
Captain, to the bridge.
( alarm sounding )
Report.
WORF:
This energy vortex has
just appeared beneath us.
There was no warning.
Well, at least
the waiting's over.
Captain's log, supplemental.
We have apparently
intersected with...
something.
It is similar to our
tractor beam, sir,
only much more powerful.
Bridge,
this is Lieutenant La Forge.
Bridge.
The pull on the Enterprise
is steady.
I'm having to hold
the warp engines at 30%
in order to maintain
our present position.
Transfer engineering control
to the bridge.
On my way, Captain.
Captain, there is
a consciousness here.
Not thought--
more like instinct.
What do you think,
Number One?
I think we're being probed.
The beam is coming
from the center of the vortex.
Sensors show it to be
only a mass
of energy.
What is it trying to learn?
I think it's trying
to determine
if we are a life-force.
We'll stay and investigate.
RIKER:
Agreed.
Unless that was the mistake.
Staying too long.
Possibly.
We should go now.
Well...
That would be
the prudent move.
I never thought I'd hear myself
saying something like that.
Under the circumstances, sir,
I think you're right.
But you would rather stay
and find out what it is?
What is its intent?
( door opens )
Engineering, transfer to bridge.
Mr. La Forge.
Sir?
Try and take us out of here,
maximum warp.
Aye, sir.
I've set the velocity
at warp nine.
Engage.
Warp engines are at 91%.
Put it to the wall,
Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
( alarm sounding )
I can't hold it.
Captain, the engines
can't handle the strain.
All stop.
PICARD:
Mr. La Forge!
I'm re-engaging
warp engines, Captain.
Status?
All decks have reported.
No damage, no injuries.
Captain, the hold
on the Enterprise
is still very strong.
I'm having to hold at warp seven
just to maintain our position.
Everything we do
tightens its grip.
Let's see what
we can learn.
Launch a class-1 probe.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf...
That was personal.
Captain, the power drain needed
to hold this position
is enormous.
How long can you maintain it?
Just a few minutes
and then we're going
to have to shut down again.
PULASKI:
Captain, some kind of energy
just surrounded my patient.
Is he alive?
Yes.
Arm the photons,
Mr. Worf.
Lock on the center
of the vortex.
Photon torpedoes locked
on target.
Hold for my order.
Like a rag
in a dog's mouth.
I am now at maximum warp.
It's you, Captain.
It was the entire ship,
but now it has focused
its attention
entirely on you.
Captain,
I can't hold it any longer.
If we don't shut down
right now, we are going...
Hold this position.
Counselor, if I were
to leave the Enterprise,
would its attention
still be focused on me?
Yes, I think it would.
You'd never survive.
But in those
few seconds,
the Enterprise
might break free.
That's what he...
that's what the other Picard
must have thought.
Captain, where are you going?
You have the bridge, Number One.
You're leaving
the ship?
We may be on a road
that has no turns.
He's very
agitated.
I must get to the shuttle.
I know.
Do you know where you are?
The Enterprise.
Yes, but you're
only vaguely aware of it.
And me...
do you know who I am?
No, you don't, do you?
I must go.
Release him.
Do you know what you're doing?
No. Release him.
Security to Sick Bay.
PICARD:
No!
Security, disregard that order.
And clear all personnel--
repeat-- all personnel
from Shuttle Bay 2.
I don't want
any distractions.
You, stay here.
You've made a decision
to leave the ship?
I must.
Why?
The energy in the vortex
wants me.
You're certain?
Yes-- it's an entity.
A life-form
which recognizes
the Enterprise
as an entity
with me
as its brain.
And it wants me.
Shuttle Bay 2.
What's your
other option?
This is our only chance.
If I leave, it may be
distracted long enough
for the Enterprise
to escape.
You're wrong.
If you leave,
the Enterprise
will be destroyed.
Don't you remember?
You saw it happen.
If I don't
leave the ship,
then the Enterprise
will be destroyed.
If that's true,
then help me.
We want the same thing.
We both want the Enterprise
to be safe,
but there is a piece
of information
I don't have.
What is it?
It's me.
You?
RIKER:
Captain?
Yes?
We're about to lose warp drive.
Understood.
When you say it wants you,
do you mean it's still you--
only you and it's not me?
You're confusing me.
We're almost
out of time.
I must get
to the shuttle.
Wait.
You can.
I'll let you.
But first, tell me,
what is...
what was your other choice?
Stand aside.
You must tell me.
What was it?
You don't know
what I'm talking about.
You're locked
into a single intent
unable to change,
unable to alter any
of your previous actions.
I have to leave.
There's no other way.
There must be.
One, but it would never work.
What is it?
What would never work?
I have to leave.
What was
the other choice?
We can't fight, we can't escape,
we can't go forward.
No, no, we can't go forward.
That would destroy
the Enterprise.
Was that it?
Was that the other choice?
I must leave.
No.
Captain Picard!
I cannot allow you to leave.
Before we can go forward,
the cycle must end.
Dr. Pulaski,
report to Shuttle Bay 2.
Bridge.
Number One, we're wasting
our energy trying to escape.
It only weakens us.
Helm, set a course
for the center of the vortex.
Mr. La Forge, on my command,
I want all the power
you can muster.
Yes, sir.
Are we going in?
Yes.
DATA:
Course set, sir.
Now, everyone
hold their position.
No matter what.
Engage.
O'BRIEN:
Captain Picard.
This is Shuttle Bay 2.
The other Picard
and the shuttle are gone.
Explain.
They just vanished.
What's our position?
We are back on course
to Endicor.
RIKER:
Stand down
from Red Alert.
All decks have reported in.
No damage, no casualties.
You have the bridge,
Number One.
( door opens and closes )
A lot of questions,
Number One.
Damn few answers.
Maybe none of it was real.
Perhaps we were all part
of a shared illusion.
Or maybe he was
thrown back in time
so that we would be able
to take another road--
make...
make a different choice.
Well, they say
if you travel far enough,
you will eventually
meet yourself.
Having experienced that,
Number One,
it's not something
I would care to repeat.
I'll be on the bridge, sir.