Captain's log,
Stardate 42686.4.
We are en route
to Starbase Montgomery
for engineering consultations
prompted by minor readout
anomalies.
I would consider them
insignificant.
What if you're wrong?
Sorry.
But what if it is more
than mere discrepancy?
Then I'd say we have a problem.
Agreed. We will have
Starbase Montgomery
give us
an independent reading.
Even if the molecular level
controls have failed,
we can still recrystalize
the dilithium
without
outside help.
Don't worry, Data.
My ego isn't
at stake here.
Perhaps we can
reprogram
the system to correct
the readout variables.
Well, that's certainly
another option.
But as we are stopping at
Starbase Montgomery anyway,
we'll let them
do the analysis.
I don't recall
Starbase Montgomery
being on the mission
itinerary.
I think we could all use
a 12-hour layover.
Besides, I've just received some
personal transfer directives,
priority matter.
Boarding or disembarking?
WESLEY:
Captain Picard.
We're within hailing range
of Starbase Montgomery.
Go to half impulse power.
Uh, will you join me
in the observation lounge
when you're done?
Captain.
Number one, I've just
been recollecting
the arrival of a new first
officer on board the Enterprise
and a manual docking,
confidently achieved.
Well, I may have been
somewhat miserly
in my congratulations
then,
so let me make up
for it now.
The captain of
the Starship Aries is retiring.
Congratulations.
You've been selected
as his replacement.
The Aries. She's
in the Vega-Omicron sector.
Mm-hmm, and they have
picked up indications
of an intelligent life-form,
though nothing confirmed.
Obviously Starfleet
will want to know more.
Well, that's why they're
asking for you.
Not for your
military proficiency
but for your skill
as an explorer
and as a diplomat.
Vega-Omicron.
That'll take months at high warp
just to get to there.
With no guarantee of finding
anything when you arrive.
Well, you have 12 hours
to think it over.
And if it's not
too premature,
congratulations, Captain.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Establish synchronous orbit.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Starbase Montgomery is sending
a civilian advisor on board
to brief you
on the Aries's mission.
A personal briefing?
Mm-hmm.
A strategic attaché
with a specialized knowledge
in the frontier regions.
I think you'll find
the briefing interesting.
I hope it's complete.
Much of my decision
will be based on it.
O'BRIEN:
Commander Riker
to transporter room three.
Enjoy.
Ensign.
Ah, you're right on time,
Commander.
He's on his way now.
Dad.
You're the civilian advisor,
in the strategic attaché?
I asked Captain Picard
to keep it quiet.
I didn't want to make you
nervous, excited.
It's been 15 years.
Excitement is hardly
the appropriate emotion.
You've done well.
First officer
on the Enterprise.
Quite a feather in your cap.
I've worked hard.
Of course.
I'm proud of you, son.
If you'll excuse me,
I've got my duties to attend to.
When you've settled in,
we can complete our briefing.
Have security arrange
an escort for this gentleman.
Aye, sir.
Worf, did you hear about
Commander Riker's promotion?
Yes.
He didn't know his
father was coming.
He was completely
surprised...
So?
Can you imagine
if it was your father?
I never knew my father.
And I didn't have a father
long enough to know him...
It is a waste of time
to think of such things.
I wasn't thinking about it,
but everybody needs somebody.
Enough!
You know, Starbase Montgomery
really didn't have
to send me all this help
because I've already checked
the entire dilithium spectrum
for anomalous frequencies.
So you don't have to waste
your time on that.
Wes...
You okay?
I was just talking
to Worf.
Yeah?
He's really eccentric
at times.
That's one word for it.
He was really upset.
I must have said
something wrong.
Maybe Worf's just not too
thrilled with the prospect
of losing Commander Riker
to a new assignment.
I know I'm not.
Neither am I.
But with Worf,
it was something else.
Something's really
bothering him.
Think so, huh?
Female?
No.
Career?
Family.
That is trouble.
You choose your enemies,
you choose your friends.
But family...
that's in the stars.
So I've heard.
Kyle Riker!
Excuse me,
ladies.
Great to see you.
Kyle!
It's been a long time.
This is more than a surprise,
it's total shock.
You mean you didn't
bake me a cake?
You're actually here.
That makes two of us.
How about a drink?
How about a kiss?
They know each other.
No kidding.
Well, I know her, too,
but we don't do that.
( chuckling )
You look wonderful.
DATA:
And it has nothing to do
with Commander Riker's
new assignment?
No, his reaction was just
the opposite of mine--
completely unaffected.
See, Wes?
With all that's going on,
maybe you're
overreacting.
Really?
You try talking
to Worf, Geordi.
I'm telling you,
he is not normal for Worf.
There is of course
a genetic predisposition
toward hostility
among all Klingons,
but Worf has been
unusually out of sorts.
Come on, he's never
been much on charm.
Well, whatever's troubling him,
I think we should try to help.
He is our friend.
I, for one, want
to keep him friendly.
Suggestions?
Empirical study.
Monitor the subject.
Right, watch the subject for
any signs of unusual behavior.
That won't be difficult.
Within the norm of Klingon
patterns, of course.
Discretion will be required.
Agreed.
When do we start?
We will assist you
as needed.
You found the problem.
And you must solve it.
( indistinct chatter )
Thank you.
And after working out
the Fuurinkazan
battle strategies
at the Tokyo base,
I was asked to come here
to work for Starfleet
as a tactical advisor.
I'm surprised you stayed out
of action as long as you did.
Will, please join us.
Your father and I are
just catching up.
You never told me
you knew him.
Well, it wasn't
exactly a secret.
It just never really
came up.
Sit down, son.
I'm ready for that briefing
whenever you are.
It was a pleasure.
Good to see you,
too, Graham.
Mm-hmm.
You wouldn't be running
for mayor, would you?
Do pick-up work for
the Federation long enough,
and it'll happen
to you, too.
I thought about you a lot.
Kyle, I don't need to hear
what you don't need to say.
We could have been
great together.
Possibly.
Is it true you got married?
Again.
And again.
That makes you three
for three, doesn't it?
I'm not complaining.
Each was a good man,
and we're all
still good friends.
Like us?
Close, but different.
They were all a little more
in touch with themselves.
Ah, ouch.
Face facts, Kyle.
You're crusty.
You have a reputation
for being hard as nails
and getting
the job done.
But underneath it all,
you're not so bad.
Some of us even love you.
And then there's Will.
Then there's Will.
You know, Wesley should really
be doing this on his own.
But he needs
his study time.
I can't believe
you fell for that.
I don't know, Data,
he looks perfectly normal to me.
In solitude, there is nothing
to trigger unusual behavior.
Good point.
Let's not tamper
with the status quo.
But that would defeat
the opportunity
for our
behavioral research.
In all probability,
he is simply lonely.
We can relieve his anxiety
through socialization.
Be my guest.
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
You seem to have lost the will
to communicate with others.
You have friends here.
We...
we care about you.
Why, just recently, Geordi,
Wesley, and I were saying...
With all due respect...
Be gone!
Sir.
He seems quite sincere
in his desire for solitude.
Seeing is
believing, huh?
Hm.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Worf.
May I have a moment, sir?
Of course.
What is it?
It is very
difficult to say.
Words are not always
easy for me.
Is that Earth?
Yes, Alaska.
I was nine years old.
That is a fish
you are holding.
And I didn't even catch it.
But it looks like
you were...
Hooked it.
My father took the rod away.
He wouldn't let me
reel it in.
He was afraid
that I would lose it.
You do not have good
feelings for your father?
No, I...
Well...
I'm not sure what I'm feeling.
What's on your mind?
You plan to leave
the Enterprise.
I've been offered
my own command.
I would like to join you.
I haven't accepted
the assignment yet.
But, sir, it could
be a dangerous mission.
There may be
the potential for combat.
That is not the purpose
of the mission.
Still, to die
a true hero...
Worf.
You've made
your point.
Then I know you will
do the right thing.
Finally, we're alone.
Maybe now we can talk.
I'm here for
the briefing, sir.
All you need to know is here.
These mission details
could have been transmitted.
I've been hearing
some good things about you.
And why haven't
I heard from you?
I know, keeping in touch
is not my strong suit.
It's a funny thing
about being a parent.
There aren't
any tech manuals.
No quick readouts
to get you through
the next set
of variables.
You just got to wing it
from day to day.
Will, when
your mother died...
Excuse me.
I've got to study
this mission briefing.
Will.
I came
to the Enterprise
because...
Look, considering where you
might be going, I wanted to...
I'm here with
my hand out, son.
Poor guy,
picked up the flu virus
at our last stop
at Nasreldine.
Sounds nasty.
What's the therapy?
Tryptophan-lysine
distillates
with a generous dose
of P.C.S.
P.C.S.?
Pulaski's Chicken Soup.
( laughing )
You haven't lost your touch,
have you?
I like to help.
When they hurt, I hurt.
TROI:
Dr. Pulaski's greatest medical
skill is her empathy.
You must be Commander
Riker's father.
Yes, but how...
We've heard about you,
and I felt certain things.
This is Deanna Troi,
ship's counselor.
Kyle Riker.
I thought
you two should meet.
Deanna's job is
to keep us from
deluding ourselves.
Let me guess.
Betazoid?
At your service.
I have some lab work to do.
If you'll excuse me.
Why do I get the feeling
that this is a setup?
Because you are intelligent,
wise, and quite correct.
Well I've never been setup
better, that's for sure.
You're also very
anxious about something.
It's Will, isn't it?
You are not as close to him
as you'd like to be.
Oh, I don't know.
We both have pretty good taste
in women, wouldn't you say?
I'd like to help you,
if I can.
If you'll let me.
Fine. What is it
you want from me?
I came here to bury
the hatchet with my son
only to find out that
the ground was frozen solid.
You don't seem to be
the kind to give up so easily.
I didn't say
I was giving up.
It would just be nice to get
a little something from him.
What is it
you want from him?
I don't know.
Acknowledgement,
maybe or...
Respect is earned,
not bestowed.
Respect?
I don't need that from him.
Perhaps you want him
to be proud of you.
You carry great pride
in his accomplishments.
Absolutely.
Look at him. First officer
of the Enterprise.
Just been offered
his first command.
Yet, you covet his success.
Please.
He'd be lucky to have
the career I've had.
True, you are well-respected
in your field.
I may have something
of a reputation for excellence.
And false humility.
My guess is that
Will finds you
pretty fascinating.
Candor seems to be
a trait he admires.
Honesty is the trait
he admires most.
And you should
honestly consider
why you're so competitive
with your own son.
Competitive?
Maybe in the past.
But I've come here
to help Will prepare
for his first task
as Captain.
Are you sure he'll accept
such a dangerous assignment?
He'll accept it just
because it is dangerous.
How can you be so sure?
Because I would.
And we aren't
so different,
Will and I.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Ah, you've seen
your mission briefing.
Yes, I have.
Any questions?
No, other than a question
about the Aries' first officer.
Oh, yes, his name
is Flaherty.
Yes. The briefing
mentioned something
about an uncanny
linguistic skill.
That is an understatement,
number one.
The last time
I saw Commander Flaherty,
he spoke 40 languages.
As I recall,
among the more exotic
were Romulan, Klingon,
Giamon, Stroyerian.
He speaks 40 languages?
He has this
unique ability
of instantaneously
interpreting and extrapolating
any verbal communication
that he hears.
You will find him very useful
in sector Vega-Omicron.
Yes, I'm sure I will.
( door chime )
Come in.
Oh, Captain Picard, at last.
I'd like to thank you for all
the help you've been to my son.
PICARD:
My only regret
is that your reunion
marks Will's farewell.
But he's ready
for this command.
Oh, yes.
I have no doubt.
Uh, Captain, may I have
a word with my son?
Yes, of course.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I won't be pushed
into this decision.
Oh, come on, Will.
Don't you think you're
ready for the Aries?
Starfleet does.
Of course, because you're
the best candidate for the job.
I only want you to know
I'm here if you need me.
I've been on my own
since I was 15.
I can take care of myself.
Please, spare me
the pain of your childhood.
I hung in for 13 years.
If that wasn't enough,
it's just too bad.
Data, what if I
missed something?
The ship's computer would've
corrected immediately.
Yeah, but maybe my inputs
were incorrect...
Data, Geordi...
I figured out Worf's problem.
You spoke to him?
No, no.
I accessed the complete
Klingon cultural database.
It took me some time...
Okay, Wesley.
Slow down.
What is the problem?
It's the tenth anniversary
of Worf's age of ascension.
His what?
The Klingon
age of ascension--
It's a ritual of great
significance.
A rite of initiation
marking the new level
of Klingon spiritual attainment.
And what is the significance of
the anniversary of this event?
It's a day
of celebration and ritual
spent with one's fellow
Klingons.
Worf doesn't have
any Klingon friends.
We're his friends.
Right, but we don't
practice
Klingon tradition,
and we're not Klingons.
Worf is feeling culturally
and socially isolated.
So what are
you suggesting?
I mean, I'm not sure
I want to invite
a bunch of Klingons
on board.
We can program the ship's
computer to supply
simulations on the holodeck.
Holographic Klingons.
Sure. Why not?
We need only
to program the computer
with details
of the specific ceremony.
No, the cultural
database said
that the Klingon's family
must attend.
So, we're his family.
We'll go.
I just wonder what kind of party
the Klingons had in mind.
Have you got a minute?
Sure.
I wanted to apologize for
my remark in ten-forward.
Your personal life is
none of my business.
Even if it involves
your father?
Even if it
involves my father.
Did he ever tell you
why he never remarried?
What woman would have him
with an ego like that?
I would have.
In a cold minute.
12 years ago, Kyle Riker
was a civilian strategist
advising Starfleet in its
conflict with the Tholians.
The Starbase that
he was operating from
was attacked.
None of the base crew
was expected to live.
And they all died.
All except your father.
Your father alone had
the will to endure,
to face the pain, to live.
I never knew
any of that about him.
I've never seen a man
fight so hard in all my life.
And you fell in love?
Yes, and so did he.
But marriage was
out of the question.
He had other priorities.
His career.
You know, if I were you,
going out on the Aries,
I'd jettison
the emotional baggage
you're still
carrying around.
Now, the Klingon
cultural database
was very specific
on the setting.
Now let me guess.
20-piece orchestra,
magnificent ballroom,
everyone in formal wear.
No, there was
some unusual test
of inner strength involved.
That would entail the use
of Klingon "painstiks."
Painstiks?
Sounds lovely.
Enduring
physical suffering is
considered a Klingon
spiritual test.
You mean, in order for Worf
to celebrate the anniversary
of this ascension,
he has to be hurt?
And we have
to witness this?
We are his family.
( door chime )
Come.
Number one.
I'd be a fool to turn
that promotion down, wouldn't I?
I don't know.
And if you're asking me
what I think you should do,
I don't know that, either.
I can spell out for you,
albeit crudely,
what you're
choosing between.
As the first officer
of the Enterprise,
you have a position
of distinction, prestige,
even glamour of a sort.
You are the second in command
of Starfleet's flagship.
But still second in command.
Your promotion
will transfer you
to a relatively
insignificant ship
in an obscure corner
of the galaxy.
But it will be your ship.
And, being who you are,
it will soon be vibrant
with your authority,
your style, your vision.
You know...
there really is no substitute
for holding the reins.
I'll need a little more time
to make this decision.
Find anything yet?
Not yet.
There is
nothing to find.
No harm in checking,
I guess.
Really? How would you
like them to give
the transporter operation
a little once-over?
No problem.
We're totally shipshape.
You're missing the point.
It's just the idea that they
even suspect a malfunction.
If I were not a consummate
professional and an android,
I would find this entire
procedure insulting.
Thanks, Data.
Chief, would you be able
to attend a little party
for Lieutenant Worf
at 1700 hours?
A party for Worf?
Sounds intriguing, yeah.
I'd be delighted.
It's a surprise.
Oh, my lips are sealed.
I didn't want to leave
without saying good-bye.
I don't like good-byes.
How about
"until next time"?
until next time.
It's been a pleasure
working with you, Commander.
The feeling is mutual...
Counselor.
I'm supposed to know
how everyone feels,
but I can't read you
right now.
Perhaps your own feelings
are getting in the way.
My job is to help others
sort out their emotions.
My own feelings are
beside the point.
Not to me.
Our feelings are
what make us all human.
Are you feeling sad?
Yes, I am.
So am I.
I'm leaving at 2100 hours.
Can I have a minute?
I've practiced
my best Academy courtesy.
Now it's time
for you to go.
It's time for us
to have a talk.
So lower your shields.
I'm asking you to leave,
or I'll...
Or you'll what?
You know, it's a shame there's
no anbo-jyutsu ring nearby.
Really? There is.
Deck 12, the gymnasium.
We could clear the air
once and for all.
You're on.
Ah, scuttlebutt says
you wanted to see me.
That's right.
I thought
I knew you, Kyle.
You do,
as well as anyone.
Then what is this I hear about
an anbo-jyutsu match with Will?
You've heard.
Haven't we grown
beyond the point where
we resolve our problems
with physical conflict?
I think you're
overreacting.
I'm overreacting?
You're the one that's coming out
to fight with his own son.
Don't think of it
as a fight, Kate.
Think of it as more
of a contest.
And suppose
one of you is injured?
I know where to find
a good doctor.
Kate, look...
Kyle.
Will and I have been
playing anbo-jyutsu
ever since he was
eight years old,
and he knows how
to take care of himself...
and so do I.
Don't take this personally.
But Will is in his prime...
And I'm no spring chicken.
I know.
Don't worry.
He's never been
able to beat me.
Computer, is this it?
COMPUTER:
Correct.
Klingon rite
of ascension chamber.
Is this really
necessary?
If we want to get Worf
through his problem, it is.
Computer, please give us
Klingon personnel
appropriate to this event.
These images have been
specifically programmed
for ascension rites.
Cute bunch.
And they use those?
Those are
Klingon painstiks.
I once saw
one of them used
against a two-ton
Rectyne monopod.
Poor creature jumped five meters
at the slightest touch.
Finally died from excessive
cephalic pressures.
You mean...
That's right.
The animal's head
exploded like...
I think that's enough,
Chief O'Brien.
I do not enjoy riddles,
counselor.
You will enjoy this one.
I'm in no mood
for trifling or games.
Not today.
I know what an important day
this is for you.
The anniversary
of your rite of ascension.
You know about that?
All your friends
on board do.
That is impossible.
It is a secret known
only to Klingons.
And certain resourceful
young ensigns.
Wesley Crusher.
What does he know
about it?
Just bear with me.
Where are we going?
The holodeck.
This is truly trying
my patience, Counselor.
I think you
will approve.
You're not coming in?
No.
Open.
An ascension ceremony.
GEORDI:
Happy anniversary, Worf.
Shall we begin?
I am ready.
( speaking Klingon )
Today...
I am a warrior.
I must show you my heart!
I travel
the river of blood!
( screaming )
The true test
of Klingon strength
is to admit one's
most profound feelings
while under
extreme duress.
( heavy breathing )
( speaking in Klingon )
( screaming )
The battle is mine.
I crave only the blood
of the enemy.
( speaking in Klingon )
( screaming )
The bile of the vanquished
flows over my hands.
( speaking in Klingon )
( screaming )
Thank you.
Is Lieutenant Worf
all right?
He's never been happier.
So it was a good ceremony?
Well, let's just say
that I was not about
to stay around
for refreshments.
Klingon culture is
not in your taste?
I'm just glad
that humans have progressed
beyond the need
for barbaric display.
Have they?
Commander Riker
and his father
are in the gymnasium,
about to engage
in a barbarism of their own.
Don't remind me, it's something
of which I do not approve.
In spite of human evolution,
there are still some traits
that are endemic to gender.
You think that they're going
to knock each other's brains out
because they're men?
Human males are unique.
Fathers continue to regard
their sons as children
even into adulthood.
And sons continue to chafe
against what they perceive
as their fathers'
expectations of them.
It's almost as if they never
really grow up at all, isn't it?
Perhaps that's part
of their charm...
and why we find them
so attractive.
Particularly men
like Commander Riker.
And his father.
I hope they don't
injure each other.
Anbo-jyutsu, the ultimate
evolution in the martial arts.
I remember
my early lessons.
You could never get used
to the sightless factor...
or to losing.
True.
But I've had
15 years to practice.
Well, let's see
if you've learned anything.
( ceremonial chant
in Japanese )
Uhh!
Well...
You've been practicing.
And remembering.
You should have been
the one to die, not her.
( repeats ceremonial chant )
Good, get it all out.
( ceremonial chant )
Agh!
Matta!
I had you.
Listen, Will.
You were too young
to understand.
And I was
too hurt to explain.
You were never
too hurt for anything.
She was your mother.
But she was my wife.
And when she died,
all that kept me
going was you.
You had a strange way
of showing it.
I came here thinking
we could talk this out.
But maybe you're right.
Maybe I am no father.
And you're no son.
And this fight is
all we have left.
( both grunting )
Matta!
What is it now?
You can't do that.
What?
Hachidan kiritsu.
It's illegal.
You're kidding.
All these years...
that's why I never won.
You were cheating.
( chuckling )
It worked, didn't it?
Kept you coming
back for more.
Incredible.
You cheated me.
How did you get away with it?
You were just a kid.
By the time
you were 12 years old,
I knew I couldn't take you.
But I had to keep you
interested.
I had to keep you
challenged, didn't I?
I always
hated you for that.
Damn it, Will!
You were barely out of diapers
when she died.
You hardly knew her!
I loved her.
Of course you carried
the pain, so did I.
I should have explained this
to you a long time ago,
but it hurt too much.
Then the wall grew up
between us.
Living there,
you and me,
the wall got bigger.
You know...
it's funny.
I can talk to a whole
roomful of admirals
about anything
in the galaxy,
but I can't talk to you
about how I feel.
How do you feel?
How do you think?
I love you, son.
I've got to get back
to the Starbase.
I know.
I'm glad you came.
Be careful now, okay?
Starbase Montgomery's
briefing specialist
and analytical team
have beamed down, sir.
Ah, what were the analytical
team's findings?
They suggested
we reprogram the system
to correct
the readout variables.
Precisely what Commander Data
recommended, as I recall.
At least it gave
Commander Riker
the opportunity to consider
his promotion.
Now that he's accepted,
we can leave him
at Starbase Montgomery.
Number one?
Captain...
with your permission,
I've decided to stay
on board the Enterprise.
Granted.
Thank you, sir.
Take us out of orbit,
Ensign Crusher.
Breaking synchronous
orbit, sir.
Set course for Beta Kupsic.
That is still
our destination?
Mm-hmm.
Velocity, warp factor 5.
Course and speed set, sir.
Any particular reason
for this change of heart?
Motivated self-interest.
Right now, the best place
for me to be is here.
Engage.