Captain's log,
Stardate 42695.3.
We're the first manned vessel
to enter
the Selcundi Drema sector.
Unmanned probes have
recorded unusual levels
of geological activity
in all five planetary systems.
I am hoping the Enterprise will
find the answer to this enigma.
Commander, I've been reviewing
the unmanned probe scans.
At some point
during the last 150 years,
the fifth planet
of Selcundi Drema has shattered,
forming an asteroid belt.
I'd call that
geological instability.
Is there any indication
that this is the work
of an unknown
intelligence?
This is geology,
not malevolence.
These planets live fast
and die hard.
The question is why.
You sure won't reconsider?
No. I'll just watch you
and be impressed.
Optimistic vote of confidence
from the non-rider.
You know
I never particularly thought
of you as an animal person.
Small animals, no.
But horses...
Computer, program the holodeck
for a woodland setting
with a bridle path
and an appropriate mount.
Type of mount...
Andorian Zabathu?
Klingon Sark...?
Horse, Earth horse.
Breed?
Arabian.
The Arabs believed that Allah
gathered the South winds
and made the horse.
On the holodeck, we've made
that legend come true.
I like that.
Oh yes, computer,
English tack
and I will control
the animal myself.
Enter when ready.
So you like horses
for the romance.
Oh it goes deeper than that.
A fine war horse would sleep
in a Bedouin's tent,
carry him into battle,
feed his children
with her milk.
There's a bond which is
created by mutual need.
Hello, beautiful.
Now I understand.
You don't want
the comfort of a pet,
you want a companion.
Thank you.
I don't want
to anthropomorphize anything.
It seems that some creatures
have the capacity
to fill spaces
you never knew were empty.
I had a Betazoid
kitten once.
My mother and the cat reacted
badly to one another.
Sure you don't want to try?
It's very relaxing.
We can find you something
that will be quiet and gentle.
No I prefer a mode
of transportation
that doesn't have
a mind of its own.
Strange.
I would expect Betazoids to be
outstanding animal trainers.
We become too involved
in the thoughts and shifting
passions of the beast.
We lose our way
and get swept up in emotion.
I would have thought the
shifting passions of this beast
would be far more terrifying.
RIKER:
Captain.
Yes, Number One?
We've entered
the first system.
I think you might
want to come to the Bridge.
Something interesting?
Spectacular,
and a little terrifying.
I'm on my way.
( door opens )
The first long-range reading,
magnification ten to the sixth.
Quite impressive.
And deadly.
The last unmanned probe showed
a thriving ecosystem.
Now, there's nothing.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
This is Commander
Riker's meeting.
I'll need your advice
and your recommendations.
As you know I have been
given the responsibility
of overseeing
Wesley's education.
To further that goal,
I would like
to put him in charge
of the planetary mineral
surveys.
That's a big job
with a lot of responsibility.
The game isn't big enough
unless it scares you a little.
To do the job,
Wesley is going to need a team.
It takes command
presence to lead.
You think he's ready for that?
Leadership grows
from self-confidence,
which is also part of
a Starfleet officer's education.
All of this is true.
But there's
an old horse trainer's adage
about putting too much weight
on a young back.
We don't want him
to break under pressure.
PULASKI:
We seem to be shifting
the focus here.
Are we talking about
a young officer
on the fast track
to the academy,
or are we talking
about a young man
that we're guiding through
adolescence and into adulthood?
TROI:
You can't guide
someone into adulthood.
The experiences are unique
to each person.
Whether Wes succeeds
or fails,
he will learn
from the experience.
I agree.
I'm just questioning
the speed at which we're moving.
You think we're pushing him
too hard?
I think that's a valid concern.
Tempering is taken
to extremes.
He is a boy, not a sword.
Who will one day become a man.
And to extend the metaphor
will need a fine edge
that won't dull
at the first touch
of resistance.
Sooner or later he'll have
to feel the burden of command.
Ensign Crusher,
report to the observation
lounge.
RIKER:
Wesley,
I've assigned you the command
of the planetary
mineral surveys.
Sir?
Thank you, sir.
Well, you may not thank me
after you see how much work
it entails.
Assemble a team.
Take a look at the records
of the Drema Quadrant.
There's a mystery here.
We've got to solve it.
Yes, sir.
A team, sir?
Ensign, this is a serious
responsibility.
I know, sir.
These officers are here
to assist you.
Not judge,
help you.
You should make use
of them.
They are a valuable resource.
And by the way,
I respect an officer
who is prepared to admit
ignorance and ask a question
rather than one who,
out of pride,
will blunder blindly forward.
I understand, sir.
Ensign.
You're dismissed.
I'll try not
to disappoint you.
WORF:
Is this part
of your regular duties?
No, it is a personal project.
I have reset the sensors
to scan for frequencies
outside their usual range.
Hmm. Such as?
The dips and peaks
of the galaxy's
magnetic field,
organic molecules
in nebular clouds,
energetic cosmic rays.
Interesting.
Would these scans also detect
artificial transmissions
as well as naturally
occurring signals?
Of course.
Good.
Those signals
are very faint
and difficult to distinguish
from background noise.
That is why I am
boosting the power.
I will be removing
that equipment to my quarters.
Good.
( chuckles )
Hi, can I walk with you?
Yes.
I need a little advice.
Well, it's free.
Walking or advice?
Both.
It's about my team.
I'm considering so many factors,
I'm confusing myself.
What have you done so far?
Well, I've broken
down the task
and picked the best people
in those disciplines.
So who have you got
so far?
I've got Prixus in mineralogy
and metallurgy.
Alans and Hildebrant for
volcanology and geomechanics.
I want Davies
for geo-chemistry, but...
TROI:
But they're all much
older than you are.
Right. And it makes me
feel strange. I mean...
what do I do
about personality conflicts?
Completely irrelevant.
These people are professionals.
If there's
a personality conflict,
you're in charge--
you settle it.
So you not only have
to understand the job,
you also have to be
a ship's counselor?
Sometimes.
Well, thank you.
Captain's log,
stardate 42696.3.
We are entering the second
Selcundi star system
where acting Ensign Crusher
will begin his planetary
mineral survey,
the results of which may help
unlock the geological puzzle.
Ensign Davies?
You got him.
Wesley Crusher.
I've been put in charge
of the the planetary
geological surveys.
And I'd like you
on my team.
Sounds great.
Who else is on it?
I have Prixus, and Alans,
and Hildebrant.
Ah, it's a shame you didn't
talk to me first.
It's just personal opinion,
but I like to break up
married teams.
Hmm,
I hadn't thought of that.
Don't worry.
They'll probably
work out fine.
And, uh, if you need any help,
just give me a signal
and I'll take over for you.
We don't want you to get
too beat up
on your first command.
Uh... thanks, but I'm
pretty sure I'll be all right.
Computer, identify please.
Sensors indicate low-level
R.F. waves.
Is there a pattern?
Affirmative.
Naturally occurring?
Negative.
Key universal translator,
please.
Unable to comply.
Weak signal.
Lock on com link and boost.
Lock on complete.
Read, please.
( screeching static )
Insufficient signal strength.
Enhance, please.
GIRL:
Is anybody out there?
Yes.
Wes.
Hi, Dr. Pulaski.
Is there trouble
behind that door?
My team's in there.
I've got to assign planets,
set a schedule.
It sounds like you've got
everything under control.
I haven't had to deal
with them yet.
Not together,
not professionally.
Wes, the minute you walk
through that door,
they're your team.
You have nothing
to prove.
You've got the authority.
That's just 'cause
Commander Riker says I do.
It's up to you
to hang on to it.
You better get in there.
And Wes...
for whatever it's worth,
I think you're
gonna do just fine.
Captain's log,
Stardate 42737.3.
It has been six weeks
since our entrance
into the Selcundi Drema sector.
Each system has revealed
the same disturbing geological
upheavals on every planet.
It seems to me
at this point
we can expect the greatest
tectonic stresses.
I agree.
Nice job.
Here are the results of my scan
on the third Selcundi system.
It's just the same old song.
Didn't you tell me that U.V.
absorptions like these
are indicative
of Traker deposits?
And where there's Traker,
there's generally Dilithium?
Yes, I did.
So don't you think we ought
to run an ico-spectrogram?
Well, Wes, these Traker readings
are really faint.
It's probably just
a fool's echo.
Well, I think I'd still
run an ico-gram.
Wesley, it's
a major undertaking
to set up the scanner.
We're looking at five hours,
minimum.
I know, I know. I don't want to
do a halfway job.
Well, Wes,
there's being thorough,
and then there's
wasting time.
It's also the mark
of a good officer
to recognize the difference.
Maybe you're right.
Computer, please access
all volcanic and tectonic
plate activity in Drema 4.
Accessing.
Computer, locate Captain Picard.
Captain Picard is on holodeck 3.
Data.
An excellent steed, sir.
Sorry to disturb you,
Captain.
That's quite all right.
It must be important,
or you wouldn't be here.
Yes, sir, it is important.
Very.
Eight weeks ago,
I received a transmission--
a simple four-word message,
"Is anybody out there?"
I answered it.
There is a...
a loneliness...
inherent in that whisper
from the darkness.
Yes, sir.
I am glad you understand, sir.
But it didn't end there.
No, sir.
We speak often.
It is a young female,
humanoid.
Her society is aware
that there is
interstellar life?
No, sir.
Oops.
Just where does she think
you're calling from?
I've kept that
somewhat vague, sir.
But Sarjenka--
that is her name--
has been quite specific
telling me details
of her family and friends.
And interspersed
among these confidences
have been
some alarming references.
Go on.
Drema 4 has been enduring
the same geological stresses
we have found
in the other systems.
Then your friend is in trouble.
Yes, sir.
Well, what are you proposing?
If we can determine
the cause of these
geological disturbances,
we might be able to reverse
the process.
And violate
the prime directive?
I was hoping you might have
another option, sir.
We don't even know if this
catastrophe is preventable.
Call a conference
in my quarters.
All senior staff.
Yes, sir.
And Data...
all communication
with this life-form must cease.
Yes, sir.
I understand, sir.
( chatter )
RIKER:
...See the look
on his face.
I'll get you another drink.
Two more.
Thank you.
( whispers ):
Family emergency.
Oh.
You don't look like a person
who came here to relax.
I didn't.
I need your advice.
Yesterday,
when Ensign Davies turned in
his geological survey,
I asked him to run
an ico-spectrogram
and he didn't agree.
Do you think you were right?
Yes.
I guess...
and I could have just
been picking nits.
Or you could have
been intimidated.
It's tough to tell
other people what to do.
I suppose I could have
made it an order,
but how do you give orders
to someone who is older
and more experienced than you?
The difference in ages
between you and Davies
is not the issue here.
I guess not.
Do you think it might have
something to do with ego?
No, it's just
the opposite of ego.
Every time I try to give
an order,
something inside of me says,
what makes my judgment
so superior to these people?
Wes, responsibility
and authority go hand in hand.
Now I know you're responsible.
Now we've got to teach you
a little bit of authority.
One of the reason
you've been given command
is so you can make
a few right decisions
which will lead
to a pattern of success
and help build self-confidence.
If you don't trust
your own judgment,
you don't belong
in the command chair.
But what if I'm wrong?
Then you're wrong.
It's arrogant to think that
you'll never make a mistake.
But what if it's something
really important.
I mean, not just
a mineral survey?
What if somebody dies
because I made a mistake?
In your position, it's important
to ask yourself one question--
what would Picard do?
He'd listen
to everyone's opinion
and then make his own decision.
But he's Captain Picard.
Well, it doesn't matter.
Once Picard makes his decision,
does anyone question it?
No way.
And why not?
I'm not sure.
DATA:
Commander Riker,
report
to the Captain's quarters.
When you figure it out,
you'll understand command.
I'm on my way.
I hope I've been able to help.
You'll let me know what
you decide?
I've made my decision.
I'm gonna have Davies
run that ico-gram.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
( whispers ):
I'll see you later.
Okay.
Ensign Davies...
I want that ico-spectrogram run
on the Selcundi Drema system.
You got it.
PICARD:
It's no longer a matter
of how wrong Data was,
or why he did it.
The dilemma exists.
We have to discuss
the options.
And please,
talk freely.
There are no options.
The prime directive
is not a matter of degrees.
It is an absolute.
I have a problem
with that kind of rigidity.
It seems callous
and even a little cowardly.
Doctor, I'm sure that is not
what the Lieutenant meant.
But in situation like this,
we have to be cautious.
What we do today may profoundly
affect the future.
If we could see
every possible outcome...
RIKER:
We'd be gods,
which we're not.
If there is a cosmic plan,
is it not the height of hubris
to think that we can
or should interfere?
So what are you saying, that
the Dremans are fated to die?
I think that's an option that
we should be considering.
Consider it considered and
rejected.
If there is a cosmic plan,
are we not a part of it?
Our presence at this place,
at this moment in time,
could be a part
of that fate.
Right. And it could be a part
of that plan that we interfere.
Well, that eliminates
the possibility of fate.
DATA:
But Commander,
the Dremans are not a subject
for philosophical debate.
They are a people.
So we make an exception
in the deaths of millions?
Yes.
And is it the same situation
if it's an epidemic
and not a geological calamity?
Absolutely.
What about a war?
If generations of conflict
is killing millions,
do we interfere?
Well, now we're all
a little less secure
in our moral certitude.
What if it's not just killings?
If an oppressive government
is enslaving millions?
See, the prime directive
has many different functions,
not the least of which
is to protect us.
To prevent us
from allowing our emotions
to overwhelm our judgment.
My emotions are involved.
Data's friend
is going to die.
That means something.
To Data.
Does that invalidate
the emotion?
What if the Dremans asked
for our help?
Yes.
Sarjenka's transmission could be
viewed as a call for help.
Sophistry.
PULASKI:
I'll buy that excuse.
We're all jigging madly
on the head of a pin anyway.
She cannot ask for help
from someone she does not know.
She knows me.
What a perfectly
vicious little circle.
We are going
to allow her to die,
are we not?
Data, I want you to sever
the contact with Drema 4.
COMPUTER:
Isolating frequency.
SARJENKA:
Data? Data? Where are you?
Why won't you answer?
Are you angry with me?
Please, please, I'm so afraid.
Data. Data where are you?
PICARD:
Wait.
Oh, Data.
Your whisper from the dark
has now become a plea.
We cannot turn our backs.
Captain's log,
Stardate 42741.3.
We are entering
into orbit of Drema 4,
the planet from which Data
received the distress signal.
Sensors indicate that
the volcanic activity
is increasing.
We found the reason
for the geological instability.
Excellent.
We would have
missed it
if Ensign Crusher hadn't
requested an ico-gram.
But he did, then...
Drema 4 has the largest deposit
of Dilithium ore ever recorded.
It's also laid out
in a very unusual pattern.
The crystals are growing to form
perfectly aligned lattices.
The ore is forming
generator strata.
Which creates
a Piezoelectric effect.
In plain English,
you're saying
that the Dilithium
is causing
the geological catastrophe?
Right.
The crystals take the natural
radiant heat of a planet...
Focus it and turn it
into mechanical energy...
Which increases
tectonic stresses...
That tear
the planet apart.
And then the crystals
break down
which is why we found
all these traces of Illium-629.
So that takes care
of the why.
Now what can you do?
That is going to take
a little more work.
Can you reverse the process?
We think so.
No. No theories,
no half answers.
Yes or no?
We'll get to work
on it.
Sir...
Data's out there right now
monitoring the condition
on Drema 4.
The situation has become
pretty desperate for his friend.
He's calculated
the safest location
on the planet's surface.
You can guess why.
We're just getting deeper
and deeper in, aren't we?
She's going to die.
They're all going to die.
Unless.
Yes, unless.
All right, you can
tell Commander Data
he has my permission
to contact his, uh, his friend
and conduct her
to a safer location.
Number One, you know
where we are now?
Sir?
Sarjenka, this is Data.
Please respond.
COMPUTER:
Unable to complete transmission.
Reason for failure?
Atmospheric activity
interfering with R.F. signal.
We are modifying
class-one probes
so they become resonators.
We will then use torpedo casings
to protect them
once they begin burrowing
beneath the surface.
How will these resonators
destroy the crystals?
By emitting harmonic vibrations
which will shatter the lattices.
The Enterprise will monitor
and adjust the frequency
of the resonators.
Sounds like a plan.
Let's get started.
Captain...
Tea, Earl Grey, hot.
Captain, permission
to beam down to Drema 4.
What?
I have been unable
to contact Sarjenka.
Data, I appreciate
your concern.
Transporting to the surface
is only going to make
a bad situation worse.
Sir, I feel it is important
to determine the reason for...
Come on, Data.
Captain, your orders were
to deliver the message, correct?
Yes.
Then what is the difference
between sending the message
and delivering it personally?
A whopping big one
and you know it.
Sir, we have come this far.
In for a penny,
in for a pound.
Is that what you're saying,
Mr. Data?
Yes, sir.
Oh, hell.
Go.
Sir?
Number One, handle
the transporter.
Go.
Where would you say
we are now, sir?
O'Brien, take a nap.
You didn't see any of this,
you're not involved.
Right, sir.
I'll just be standing
over here dozing off.
Data, you've got
ten minutes, that's it.
If you see anybody
but Sarjenka...
I will signal
for immediate beam out.
PICARD:
Commander Riker to the Bridge.
Damn.
I just woke up, sir.
You know what to do?
No problem, sir.
I'll have him out of there
as smooth as ice.
( high-pitched beeping )
( beeping lowers in pitch)
Sarjenka?
Wait, I am Data.
Data.
Data, you came.
Data, where have you been?
It would take too long
to explain.
You and your family must leave.
We already have.
We ran when
the tremors began.
Then why are you here?
My father wouldn't
let us take anything,
but I had to have
my transmitter.
I knew you would come back
and I didn't want you
to find only silence,
the way I did.
I am sorry for that,
but it is very complicated.
Does your family know
where you are?
No.
You cannot survive in this.
What are we going to do?
Enterprise,
two to beam up.
You must come with me.
Where are we going?
To the stars?
There's going to be hell to pay.
Where is Commander Riker?
On the Bridge.
Where are you going?
To the Bridge.
And you are going to take that?
Don't leave me here.
Please don't leave me here.
Quite impossible.
Sir, three minutes
to resonator launch.
Where is he?
He'll be here.
He has brought
a child onto my ship
and on my bridge.
I'm sure Mr. Data has
a very good explanation.
I do, sir.
She was frightened
and did not wish
to be left...
Mr. Data, kindly
assume your station.
Counselor, will you
escort her to Sick Bay?
No, Data.
No, I'm scared.
Don't make me go.
It's all right.
No one's going to hurt you.
No.
TROI:
We'll just go and get
a treat and then...
No.
Captain, I will see to it
that she is not in the way.
One minute to launch.
Come on,
it'll be all right.
No.
Just leave me alone.
I want Data.
Counselor, allow me.
Please.
Sarjenka, no one will harm you.
These are my friends.
PICARD:
Mr. Data.
Take your station.
Keep her with you.
This does concern her.
Ten seconds.
I will require my hand.
Thank you.
Firing torpedoes.
Sensors locked on probes.
WORF:
Torpedoes have reached
their targets.
Resonators activated.
Harmonic sequences
have begun.
What are you doing?
We are attempting
to quiet your planet.
If we succeed,
there will be no more
quakes, no more volcanoes.
Ensign, when should the results
be known?
This should happen
very quickly, sir.
And my parents and brothers?
Captain, sensors indicate
a planet-wide reduction
in tectonic stress levels.
It worked.
We did it.
Your parents will be safe now.
You did this for me?
Look, Sarjenka.
There is your home.
Data...
Escort her to Sick Bay.
Aye, sir.
Number One,
you have the Bridge.
Doctor.
Yes, Captain.
Data and the alien
are on their way down.
What would be involved
in removing
all memory of her communication
with Data
and her visit to this ship?
Assuming that her brain
structure is similar to ours,
the memories would be stored
chemically
on the neurons
of the cerebral cortex.
They are also time dependent.
I would have to scan for the age
of the chemical links
and try to find
the relevant neurons.
Well, do your best.
You have many different
kinds of people here.
Yes.
When I'm bigger,
can I be on your ship?
I am certain that
you could.
I wish I could
come with you now.
I am afraid that
is not possible.
I know, but I can
still wish for it.
Dr. Pulaski...
this is Sarjenka.
Hello, Sarjenka.
Hello.
( stone sings )
What is this?
That's an Elanin singer stone.
It sings
a different song
for each person.
What does it
sing for you?
It does not sing for me.
Why not?
Because I am a machine.
Sarjenka...
we're going to run
a few scans
just to be sure
you're all right.
Data will be right here.
Don't worry.
You did a good thing, Data.
But are we doing
a good thing now, Doctor?
This is to protect her
as much as us.
By robbing her of her memories?
To remember you and this ship
would complicate her future.
She has to be the person
she was born to be.
And you'll remember.
( stone sings )
Enterprise, one to beam up.
Wes.
Sit down.
No, thank you, sir.
It's going to be a long time
before I'm qualified enough
to sit there.
You did a good job.
I'm proud of you.
Thank you, sir.
Does it get any easier?
Nope.
( door chimes )
Come.
I came to apologize, sir.
No apologies are
necessary.
You reminded us
that there are obligations
that go beyond duty.
I appreciate your seeking
other options, sir.
Your decision could have
been unilateral.
One of my officers,
one of my friends was troubled.
I had to help.
Is Sarjenka safely home?
Yes, sir.
She will not
remember me, sir.
But I will remember her.
Remembrance and regrets,
they, too, are part
of friendship.
Yes, sir.
And understanding that
has brought you a step closer
to understanding humanity.