Hot chocolate, please.
( chuckling )
We, uh, we don't
ordinarily say "please"
to food dispensers
around here.
Well, since it's listed as
intelligent circuitry, why not?
After all, working with so much
artificial intelligence
can be dehumanizing, right?
So why not combat that tendency
with a little simple courtesy?
Ah, thank you.
For someone who just arrived,
you certainly aren't shy
with your opinions.
Have I been
talking too much?
No.
Oh, I do tend to have a bit
of a motor mouth,
especially
when I'm excited.
You don't know how
exciting it is
to have gotten this assignment.
Everyone in class, I mean
everyone wants the Enterprise.
I mean it would have been
all right to spend some time
on Reina 6, do phase work
with antimatter.
That's my specialty.
I know.
That's why you got
this assignment.
I did it again.
It's just that...
I know, you're excited.
Look, Sonya...
Yes?
I don't think
you want to be around
these control stations with
that hot chocolate. Do you?
Oh, I'm sorry. I shouldn't even
have this in engineering.
It's just we were talking.
I forgot I had it
in my hand.
Um... I'm going to go
finish it over here.
Lieutenant LaForge,
this is not going to
happen again.
Oh, no, oh, I'm sorry,
oh, captain.
Actually,
it's my fault, sir.
Picard:
Indeed.
Oh, I wasn't looking.
It's all over you.
Yes, ensign,
it's all over me.
At least let me, sir.
Ensign, uh, ensign...?
Oh, Ensign Sonya Gomez.
Ensign Gomez is a recent
Academy graduate, captain.
She just transferred over
at Starbase 173.
Is that so?
Well, Ensign Sonya Gomez,
I think it will be simpler
if I simply change my uniform.
Captain, I must accept
full responsibility for this...
Yes, chief engineer.
I think I understand.
I just want to say, sir,
that I'm very excited
about this assignment,
and I promise to serve
you and my ship...
your ship, this ship
to the best of my ability.
Yes, ensign,
I'm sure that you will.
Carry on.
Oh, my.
First impressions, right?
Isn't that what they say,
first impressions
are the most important?
I'll give you this,
it's a meeting the captain
won't soon forget.
Oh.
Deck 9, officers' quarters.
Crewman, what is going on?
man:
Welcome Picard
to shuttlecraft 6.
Q.
There, there,
haven't we been careless?
A little cleaning service
I'm only too happy to provide.
We agreed you would never
trouble my ship again.
I always keep
my arrangements, sir.
Look...
we're nowhere near
your vessel.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I read your graduating thesis.
Now, I wouldn't have requested
you if you weren't the best.
Where are we going?
Ten forward.
We're going to forget
about work.
We are going sit, talk,
relax, look at the stars.
You need to learn
how to slow down.
Oh no. No, no, no,
I can't do that.
You know, you're awfully young
to be so driven.
Yes, I am.
I had to be.
I had to be the best
because only the best
get to be here.
Geordi...
lieutenant...
That's okay.
Go on.
Whatever is out here,
we're going to be
the first humans to see it.
And I want to be a part of that.
I want to
understand it.
Sonya, relax.
You're here.
You've made it.
But you won't last long
banging into walls.
It'll be there for
you, believe me.
Okay.
Look, I promise I won't let
anything exciting slip past
without letting
you know, okay?
Okay.
Bridge, this is ten forward.
Guinan, I don't remember you
ever calling the bridge before.
Is everything all right?
How do you mean?
Is there anything
unusual happening?
No, Guinan, nothing out
of the ordinary.
Why do you ask?
I'm not sure.
It's just a feeling.
I've had it a couple
of times before.
It's probably nothing.
Forget that I called.
Ten forward out.
The locator beam
won't help.
They'll never think
to look for you this far away.
Enterprise, this is Picard.
Stop this foolishness, Q.
Return me to the Enterprise.
I suggest you change
your attitude.
Petulance does not become you.
We have business, Picard.
Keeping me a prisoner here
will not compel me
to discuss anything with you.
It will in time.
I appreciate your advice,
lieutenant.
And I'll take it
to heart...
Guinan.
Can I get you something?
We're fine.
Is everything all right?
I don't know.
I um, I think I'll go
check out engineering.
I'll go with you.
Where's the captain?
In his quarters.
Captain, this is
Counselor Troi.
Computer, locate
Captain Picard.
computer:
The captain is not on the ship.
Worf:
Commander,
there's a shuttle
missing from bay 2.
All stop.
Answering all stop, sir.
I've hailed the shuttle
on all frequencies.
No response.
Data:
Sensors indicate
no shuttle
or other ships
in this sector.
I think we can assume
the captain's
aboard that shuttle.
How could he get to the
shuttlebay and leave
the Enterprise
without us knowing?
That's not possible.
Take it easy, Wes.
We're going to find him.
I want to begin
a methodical search.
Worf, set sensors
on maximum scan.
Data, use our present location
as the center.
Plot a search pattern
from these coordinates
to cover the most area
in the least time.
Search pattern
has been input, sir.
Engage, Mr. Crusher.
First officer's log,
stardate 42761.3.
We have not been able
to determine why or how
Captain Picard left
the Enterprise.
We can't even be certain
he is in the missing shuttle
although that
is the assumption
on which we are proceeding.
For the last six hours,
we have been searching
without success.
We have covered the area
in a spherical pattern
which a vessel
without warp drive
could traverse
in the time allotted.
Widen the area.
Do we stay out here
years, decades?
I'm ageless, Picard.
You are not.
The Enterprise will continue
with Riker as captain.
You are an impossibly
stubborn human.
Return me to my ship.
If I return you to your ship,
will you agree to give
my request a full hearing?
You're right, Picard.
This is the proper venue
for our discussion.
Commander, my status board
indicates the shuttle
is back in bay 2.
Computer, locate Captain Picard.
computer:
Captain Picard
is in ten forward.
I knew it was you.
You!
Picard, if you had half
the sense you pretend to have,
you would get her
off your ship immediately.
And if you like,
I'd be more than pleased
to expedite her departure.
You know him?
We have had some dealings.
Those dealings were
two centuries ago.
This creature is not
what she appears to be.
She's an imp.
And where she goes,
trouble always follows.
You're speaking of yourself,
Q, not Guinan.
Guinan?
Is that your name now?
Guinan is not
the issue here-- you are.
We had a agreement that you
would stop meddling with us.
Q:
And so I have.
What do you want, Q?
You state your business.
Get on with it.
I agree, captain.
Enough about this creature.
She's diverting us
from the purpose
of my being here.
Which is?
Ah, the redoubtable
Commander Riker
and micro-brain.
Growl for me.
Let me know
you still care.
Worf.
My purpose is
to join you.
To join us as what?
As a member of the crew.
Willing and able,
ready to serve.
This ship is already home
for the indigent,
the unwanted, the unworthy.
Why not for a homeless entity?
Homeless?
Yes.
The other members of the Q
continuum kicked you out?
Guinan:
Not all the Q
are alike.
Some are almost respectable.
Ready and willing,
able to serve.
What would you do?
Would you start
as an ordinary crewman?
Hmm?
What task is too menial
for an entity?
Sir, do you mock me?
Not at all, that's
the last thing I would do.
You by definition are
part of our charter.
Our mission is to seek out
new and different life-forms.
And you certainly qualify
as one of the most unique
I've ever encountered.
To learn about you is
frankly provocative,
but you're next of
kin to chaos.
Captain, at least allow me
to present my argument.
Worf.
After our last encounter,
I was asked to leave
the Q continuum.
Since then,
I've been wandering vaguely.
Bored, really.
My existence
without purpose.
Then I remembered all
the good times I had with you.
The good times?
The first time we met you,
you put us on trial for
the crimes of humanity.
Of which you were exonerated.
The next time we saw you,
you asked me to join
the Q continuum.
A big mistake that you
didn't accept my offer.
More and more
I realize that here, here is
where I want to be.
Think of
the advantages.
Now, I neither expect nor
require any special treatment.
And if necessary,
although I can't imagine why,
I will renounce my powers
and become as weak and as
incompetent as all of you.
No.
No?
Oh, captain, in fairness,
let me try.
I deserve at least that much.
In fairness?
You disrupt this ship,
you kidnap the captain.
I add a little excitement,
a little spice to your lives,
and all you do
is complain.
Where's your adventurous spirit,
your imagination?
Think, Picard, think.
Think of the
possibilities.
Simply speaking,
we don't trust you.
Oh, well, you may not trust me,
but you do need me.
You're not prepared
for what awaits you.
How can we be prepared
for that which we do not know?
But I do know that we are
ready to encounter it.
Really?
Yes, absolutely.
That's why we're out here.
Oh, the arrogance.
They don't have a clue
as to what's out here.
They will learn,
adapt.
That is their
greatest advantage.
They are moving faster than
expected, further than they
should.
By whose calculations?
You judge yourselves
against the pitiful adversaries
you've encountered so far.
The Romulans, the Klingons--
they're nothing
compared to what's waiting.
Picard,
you are about to move
into areas of the galaxy
containing wonders
more incredible
than you can
possibly imagine
and terrors to freeze
your soul.
I offer myself as a guide
only to be rejected
out of hand.
We'll just have to do
the best we can without you.
What justifies
that smugness?
Not smugness,
not arrogance.
But we are resolute,
we are determined,
and your help is
not required.
We'll just have to see
how ready you are.
Q!
Bridge, this is the captain.
All stop.
Wesley:
Answering all stop, sir.
Status?
According to these
coordinates,
we have traveled
7,000 light years
and are located
near the system J-25.
Travel time
to the nearest starbase?
Data:
At maximum warp,
in two years,
7 months, 3 days, 18 hours,
we would reach Starbase 185.
Why?
Why? Why, to give you
a taste of your future,
a preview of things to come.
Con permiso, capitan.
The hall is rented,
the orchestra engaged.
It's now time to see
if you can dance.
Guinan, your people have been
in this part of the galaxy.
Yes.
What can you tell us?
Only that if I were you,
I'd start back now.
Captain's log,
stardate 42761.9.
Despite Guinan's warning,
I feel compelled to investigate
this unexplored sector
of the galaxy
before heading back.
Worf:
Captain, the sixth planet
in the system is class M.
There is a series of roads
on this planet
which indicates a highly
industrialized civilization.
But where there
should be cities,
there are only great rips
in the surface.
It is though some
great force just scooped
all the machine elements off
the face of the planet.
It is identical to
what happened to the outposts
along the Neutral Zone.
Worf:
Captain.
We are being probed.
What is the source
of the probe?
A ship.
It is on an intercept course.
On screen.
Picard:
Magnify.
Riker:
Full scan.
Go to yellow alert.
Worf:
Going to yellow alert.
Riker:
Keep the shields down.
We don't want
to appear provocative.
Worf:
Aye, sir.
Mr. Data,
what can you tell us?
The ship is strangely
generalized in design.
There is no specific bridge,
no command center.
There is no engineering section.
I can identify
no living quarters.
Life signs?
Data:
There is no
indication of life.
Lieutenant Worf
what is its
alert status?
I detect no shields,
no weapons of any known design.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
No response.
This is Captain Picard
representing the United
Federation of Planets.
Guinan.
Activate your viewscreen.
I would like you to monitor
what's going on up here.
We may need your input.
I'm here, captain.
Guinan:
Viewscreen's activated.
I have the other ship.
You're familiar
with this life-form?
Yes.
My people encountered
them a century ago.
They destroyed our cities,
scattered my people
throughout the galaxy.
They're called the Borg.
Protect yourself, captain,
or they'll destroy you.
Shields up.
Aye, sir.
Riker:
All decks stand by.
Security, report
to main engineering.
We have an intruder.
Lieutenant?
Status?
It seemed to make a visual
survey of the engine core, sir.
Then it moved in here.
Interesting,
isn't it?
Not a he,
not a she.
Not like anything
you've ever seen.
An enhanced
humanoid.
What is it you want?
We mean you no harm.
Do you understand me?
Understand you?
You're nothing to him.
He's not interested
in your life-form.
He's just a scout,
the first of many.
He's here to analyze
your technology.
He may attempt to gain
control of the ship.
I wouldn't let him.
Stop.
I cannot allow you to interfere
with the operation of this ship.
Mr. Worf.
Ensign.
( groans )
Mister Worf.
Use whatever means
to neutralize the invader.
Because her people had contact
with the Borg,
I've requested Guinan to
participate in this conference.
You are aware of what occurred
just now in main engineering?
Yes.
What happened between
your people and the Borg?
I wasn't there personally.
But from what I'm told,
they swarmed
through our system,
and when they left...
there was little or nothing
left of my people.
Guinan, if they were
that aggressive, why
didn't the Borg attack?
They could have,
but they didn't.
They don't do that individually.
That's not their way.
When they decide to come,
they're gonna come in force.
They don't do
anything piecemeal.
Then the initial encounter
was solely
for the purpose
of gathering information?
Yes.
How do we reason with them,
let them know
that we're not a threat?
You don't.
At least, I've never known
anyone who did.
Worf:
Captain, we are being hailed.
On screen.
This is Captain
Jean-Luc Picard of the U.S.--
Borg:
We have analyzed your
defensive capabilities
as being unable
to withstand us.
If you defend yourselves,
you will be punished.
Hmm.
Counselor?
We're not dealing
with an individual mind.
They don't have
a single leader.
It's the collective
minds of all of them.
That would have definite
advantages.
Yes, a single leader
can make mistakes
which is far less likely
in the combined whole.
Q:
Picard?
Phew, Picard, are you
sure you don't want me
as a member of your crew?
Worf:
Captain, the Borg have
locked on to us
with some form
of tractor beam.
We're on our way.
Report, lieutenant.
Worf:
That beam is draining
our shields.
Riker:
If they pull down our shields,
we're helpless.
Warp 8, any heading.
Engage.
Captain, the beam is
holding us here.
Increase the power.
Shields weakening.
Shields will be down
in 18 seconds.
Locate the exact source
of that tractor beam.
Lock on phasers.
Phasers locked on target.
Fire.
They still have us.
Shields are down, sir.
A type of laser beam is
slicing into the saucer section.
They're carving us up
like a roast.
With whatever force necessary,
terminate that beam.
Fire when ready.
Again, Mr. Worf.
Tractor beam
is released, sir.
Force field is maintaining
our hull integrity.
Damage report?
Worf:
Coming in, sir.
Sections 27, 28, 29
on decks 4, 5, and 6 destroyed.
Casualties?
18 were in that section
and are missing.
What is the condition
of the alien ship?
They have sustained damage
to 20% of their vessel.
Life supports minimal.
Conference.
I can't get
the shields up.
Divert power
from anywhere you need it.
Anywhere except
for life support.
No, no, it wouldn't help.
The circuits that control
the shields, they've be fused.
If you can't reprogram,
then re-route.
18 people...
dead just like that.
I know, just put it out
of your head.
No, I can't.
I keep seeing them.
Sonya, stop it.
We'll have time to grieve later.
Now, right now, let's just get
these shields operative.
Hmm?
Right. Right.
Of course.
Guinan, how much more can you
tell us about these creatures?
Bits and pieces.
Anything would help.
They're made up of organic
and artificial life
which has been developing
for thousands of centuries.
Q:
The Borg is
the ultimate user.
They're unlike any threat
your Federation has ever faced.
They're not interested
in political conquest,
wealth, or power
as you know it.
They're simply interested
in your ship-- its technology.
They've identified it
as something they can consume.
You brought us here,
you exposed us to it,
and you cost us
the lives of our shipmates.
Oh, please.
Number One.
18 of our people have died.
Please, tell us
this is one of your illusions.
Oh, no, this is as real
as your so-called life gets.
Geordi:
This is Lieutenant LaForge,
captain.
We have been able to restore
power to the shields.
Very good.
Worf:
Captain, I have the casualty
list coming on screen.
Cancel.
We'll deal with that later.
Sir, if we're going to have any
further dealings with the Borg
now or in the future,
I think we should find out
all we can about them.
Visit their ship?
In my opinion,
that's the only choice.
Assemble a minimal away team.
Guinan:
What?
Mr. Worf,
Transporter room 3.
Data.
I wouldn't go there
if I were you.
I don't know Guinan,
they paid us a visit.
It seems only fair that
we return the courtesy.
Captain's log, supplemental.
We have been attacked
without provocation
by an alien race
which Guinan calls the Borg.
It appears that we have
neutralized their vessel.
Commander Riker is leading
an away team
in an attempt
to learn more about them.
There are
no life sign readings.
I've laid in
coordinates
that should set you down in
the least damaged section
of the Borg ship.
Set phasers on stun.
Be ready to increase power
in case we need it.
Energize.
I wonder why they
don't react to us
or why the Enterprise
didn't read any life signs,
especially with this
many of them.
Perhaps because this ship
was being scanned
for individual
life signs.
Apparently when
they are in these slots,
they become
a part of the whole
and no longer read
as separate life-forms.
Captain.
Go ahead, Number One.
Our readings were incorrect.
The Borg crew survived.
They appear to be
in some kind of stasis.
Picard:
Explain.
There are slots along
the wall,
kind of like compartments,
there are two Borg in each one.
Captain, I would theorize
that the Borg are somehow
interconnected
through these slots,
and they are working
collectively.
We're going to try to access
their main computer.
Commander.
I believe each
slot is designed
for a specific Borg.
Here is where the
connection is made.
Like a juggernaut.
It could begin moving
at any moment.
The technology required
to achieve
this biological
and artificial interface
is far beyond
our capabilities.
There are many advantages.
Speed being
the most obvious.
This ship literally
just thinks what it wants,
and then it happens.
Fascinating.
They either don't see us
or don't see us
as a threat.
Transporter chief.
O'Brien here, captain.
Picard:
If your fix on the away team
wavers in the slightest,
beam them back immediately.
Count on it, sir.
Captain,
this is incredible.
We've entered what appears
to be the Borg nursery.
Picard:
Describe it.
From the look of it,
the Borg are born
as a biological life-form.
It seems...
that almost immediately
after birth,
they begin
artificial implants.
Apparently the Borg have
developed the technology
to link artificial intelligence
directly
into the humanoid brain.
Astounding.
Commander.
What is it?
The ship appears
to be regenerating.
Perhaps this explains
why they have not
taken notice
of our presence.
Their collective effort
is being directed
into repairing this vessel.
Captain.
The Borg seem to be using
their combined power
to repair the ship.
Transporter chief,
beam the away team
directly to the bridge.
Picard:
Let's get the hell
out of here, warp 8.
Now, Mr. Crusher, engage.
Captain, the Borg
are in pursuit.
On screen.
Picard:
Magnify.
Riker:
Increase to ten
to the third power.
It's continuing
to regenerate.
Let's see
if we can out run them.
Mr. LaForge, I want maximum warp
for as long as we can hold it.
Yes, sir.
We are now passing warp 8.5.
Eight point eight.
Warp 9.
Arm the photon torpedoes.
Let's see if we can
slow them down.
Torpedoes armed.
Fire.
They had no effect.
Geordi:
Bridge, this is engineering.
We are now at warp 9.65.
The Borg are
still gaining.
They will follow
this ship
until you exhaust
your fuel.
They will wear down
your defenses.
Then you will be theirs.
Admit it, Picard.
You're out of your league.
You should have stayed
where you belonged.
Captain's log, supplemental.
We are unable
to maintain the gap
between the Enterprise
and the Borg ship.
Geordi:
Engineering to bridge.
Go ahead.
You've got
all we can give you.
I understand,
Mr. LaForge.
Captain, the enemy vessel
is firing on us.
There are no reports
of any damage to the Enterprise.
Captain, the target
was not the ship.
The weapon was designed
to drain the shields.
Confirmed.
Shield effectiveness
has been reduced 12%.
Captain, the Borg
ship is closing.
They're firing again.
Shields have been
reduced 41%.
Another hit,
and we will be defenseless.
Arm the photon torpedoes.
Torpedoes armed.
Fire the photons.
The Borg ship was not damaged.
You can't outrun them.
You can't destroy them.
If you damage them, the essence
of what they are remains.
They regenerate
and keep coming.
Eventually you
will weaken.
Your reserves
will be gone.
They are relentless.
The Borg ship is firing.
We have lost
shields again.
Captain, we've just lost
the warp engines.
Q:
Where's your stubbornness
now, Picard, your arrogance?
Do you still profess
to be prepared
for what awaits you?
The Borg ship is re-establishing
its tractor beam.
Lock on photon torpedoes.
Worf:
Yes, sir.
Without our shields,
at this range
there is a high degree
of probability
that a photon detonation
could destroy
the Enterprise.
Prepare to fire.
I'll be leaving now.
Q:
You thought you could
handle it, so handle it.
Q.
End this.
Moi?
What makes you think
I'm either inclined
or capable
to terminate this encounter?
If we all die here, now,
you will not be able
to gloat.
You wanted to frighten us.
We are frightened.
You wanted to show us
that we were inadequate.
For the moment, I grant that.
You wanted me to say
I need you.
Position?
Zero seven zero
mark six three, sir.
Back where we started.
That was
a difficult admission.
Another man would have been
humiliated to say those words.
Another man would have rather
died than ask for help.
I understand what
you've done here, Q.
But I think the lesson
could have been learned
without the loss
of 18 members of my crew.
If you can't take
a little bloody nose,
maybe you ought to go back home
and crawl under your bed.
It's not safe out here.
It's wondrous with treasures
to satiate desires
both subtle and gross.
But it's not for the timid.
Mr. Crusher,
set course
for the nearest starbase.
Course laid in
for Starbase 83, sir.
Engage.
Q set a series
of events into motion
bringing your contact
with the Borg
much sooner than
it should have come.
Now, perhaps
when you're ready,
it might be possible
to establish
a relationship with them.
But for now,
for right now,
you're just
raw material to them.
Since they're aware
of your existence...
They will be coming.
You can bet on it.
Maybe Q did the right thing
for the wrong reason.
How so?
Well, perhaps
what we most needed
was a kick
in our complacency,
to prepare us
for what lies ahead.