( groaning )
( door opens )
Number One, will
you join me in
the Ready Room?
Yes, sir.
( breathing heavily )
I've just come from a meeting
with Admiral Moore.
He wanted to discuss this.
( electronic pulsing )
Recognize it?
Sounds like it might be
an SOS.
Good guess.
You're quicker
than Starbase Research.
It took them hours to determine
that this was a distress beacon.
When was it detected?
Last month.
It just kicked in
without any warning.
Who used the beacon?
It's Terran.
Captain, I'm familiar with
most Earth codes, and...
Mm-hmm.
Interesting.
Yes, that code hasn't been
used in centuries.
What was its
origin point?
Ficus Sector.
Captain, I don't think
there's any record
of an Earth colony
in that area.
Well, now we know
there's someone out there
and they're
asking for help.
But who?
Let's try and find out.
Computer, download
all information
regarding signal beacon
from Starbase mainframe.
COMPUTER:
Distress beacon used
by the European Hegemony.
The European Hegemony?
A loose alliance formed in the
early part of the 22nd century.
It was the first
stirrings
of world government.
You should read more history,
Number One.
Computer, locate
the exact dates
in which this signal beacon
was in general use.
Old Earth calendar
2123 until 2190.
No extraterrestrial source
ever used this code?
COMPUTER:
Negative.
Computer, locate all Earth
deep space launches
from 2123 until 2190
with the destination in
or near the Ficus Sector.
Working.
Nothing for Ficus.
Damn it, who's out there?
Lost sheep.
Let's go see if we
can find them.
Medical emergency.
Dr. Pulaski to the Bridge.
PICARD:
What happened?
He just
collapsed, sir.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's log,
stardate 42823.2.
We are departing
from Starbase 73
to investigate the source
of a mysterious
distress signal.
Meanwhile, my security officer
remains in Sick Bay
where Dr. Pulaski is searching
for the cause of his collapse.
I am fine.
You're not fine.
You fainted.
I did not faint.
Klingons
do not faint.
Excuse me, I'll rephrase.
This Klingon suffered
a dramatic drop
in blood pressure.
His blood glucose
level dropped.
There was deficient blood flow
resulting
from circulatory failure.
In other words,
he curled up his toes
and lay unconscious
on the floor.
Doctor, there is no
need to insult me.
Worf, I'm worried.
Now, something is wrong.
Klingons don't faint.
( growls )
Forgive me.
I just can't think
of another word that applies.
You're sick.
Klingons do not give in to...
Just stay
right where you are.
I have to check something
with the computer.
Lieutenant, you have rop'ngor.
But that is a
childhood ailment.
Yes.
How shall I live down
the humiliation?
Oh, Worf, you can't help...
Still, for a warrior
to find himself
in such a situation.
So you've got the Klingon
version of the measles.
How would Commander Riker feel
if he had the measles?
Pretty silly.
PICARD:
Dr. Pulaski, how is
Lieutenant Worf?
He's in no danger.
Uh, Worf was, um...
just observing
a Klingon ritual
involving fasting
and he didn't take into account
that you have to decrease
your physical activity
as you decrease
your caloric intake.
Pulaski out.
Thank you.
I am in your debt.
( deep exhale )
( door chime )
Come.
Captain, I've been considering
the problem of the missing ship.
Although there is no record
of a launch
to the Ficus Sector--
which would not be unusual
considering the chaos
of the early 22nd century--
someone had to load that ship.
The manifest.
Yes, sir.
There it is.
SS Mariposa.
Loaded 27th of November 2123.
Destination Ficus Sector.
Captain Walter Granger,
commanding.
Mariposa: the Spanish word
for butterfly.
Thank you, Data.
I thought it might be
significant, sir.
It doesn't appear to be, Data.
No, sir.
You learn a lot about people
from their luggage--
225 Yoshimitsu computers,
five monitor beacon satellites
700 cellular com links,
fifty spinning wheels...
Spinning wheels?
Cattle...
Accessing.
chickens,
pigs...
A device used for spinning yarn
or thread, which consists
of a large hand
or foot-driven
wheel and once...
Why would anyone carry
such an insane mix of cargo?
Data!
Perhaps they were planning
for the worst, sir.
Theorize, Data.
Give me some background.
In the early
22nd century
Earth was recovering
from World War III.
A major philosopher of the time
was Liam Dieghan
founder
of the Neo-Transcendentalists
who advocated a return
to a simpler life
in which one lived
in harmony with nature
and learned
under her gentle tutelage.
Thank you, Data.
But if this was a ship
full of utopians
why carry all this
technological baggage?
I have insufficient
information
upon which to form
a cogent theory, sir.
Doctor.
I wish to thank you
for protecting my...
Your secret
is safe with me.
Worf, I'm honored.
No one has ever performed
the Klingon tea ceremony for me.
There, that
should do it.
You know the ceremony.
I understand the externals,
not the mysteries.
I'm not a Klingon.
You must not drink the tea.
It is deadly to humans.
And none too good for Klingons.
It is a test of bravery,
of one's ability
to look at the face
of mortality.
It is also a reminder
that death is
an experience best shared
like the tea.
Worf, you're a romantic.
It is among the Klingons
that love poetry
achieves its fullest flower.
Hold that thought.
Antidote.
If we're going to share,
let's share.
Now, quote me a little
of that poetry.
PICARD:
Initiate sensor sweeps.
Aye, sir.
The system's sun
has entered a period
of severe
flare activity.
Now we know what
triggered the SOS.
Class-M readings
from the fifth planet
in the system.
Take us in.
WORF:
Shields
at maximum.
Sensors indicate
human life-form readings
30 meters below
the planet's surface.
Hailing on all frequencies.
No response so far
but the flares may be
interfering with communications.
There is no evidence
of an advanced
communication network.
They brought a lot
of technology.
Where is it?
There is no artificial
power source on the planet.
The stellar flares
are increasing
in magnitude and frequency.
Computer projections indicate
they will brush the planet
in 3.6 hours.
Evacuation will be difficult.
We can lower our shields
for transport
only between the flares.
Captain, these people have
been isolated for 300 years.
They could be very
unsophisticated.
The shock of being suddenly
transported onto a space ship
could frighten them,
to say the least.
Mm. Your point is well-taken,
Counselor.
Number One, you're going
to have to go down there.
On my way.
Captain's log,
stardate 42827.3.
Commander Riker
has reached the caverns
where he's making preparations
to begin the evacuation.
What's the situation,
Number One?
RIKER:
There are roughly
200 people down here.
Their condition?
Surprisingly good.
Are they willing to leave?
Yes, but...
Well, get them up here.
I'm having a little debate
with the colony's leader.
It seems...
There's no time, Number One.
Initiate the transport.
But, sir...
Whatever the problem,
we'll handle it up here.
Aye, aye, sir.
We're on our way, all of us.
Riker out.
RIKER:
First load ready, Mr. O'Brien.
Energizing.
( sheep baaing )
( rooster crowing )
Captain
you'd better get somebody
down here, right away.
( sheep baaing,
rooster crowing over com )
( pig squealing )
MAN:
Down you go, my beauty.
Down you go.
Take the pig out there,
will you?
Very good, very good.
O'Brien, I think that third wave
should be in position.
Shoo, damn you.
Shoo, shoo.
Aye, sir.
( loud commotion,
chicken clucking )
O'Brien, is it, hmm?
I should have known
'twould be
a good Irishman
who was running
this ship.
( clears throat )
What the devil is going
on here, Number One?
Ah, Captain Picard, is it?
Oh, the man who makes
decisions for me and mine
without so much
as a by-your-leave.
This is my Security
Chief, Lieutenant Worf.
I don't suppose security
is much of a problem for you.
Danilo Odell, sir,
at your service.
What are these animals
doing here, Number One?
I'm sorry, sir.
It was either this or arguing
until hell froze over.
Uh, Captain
Picard, sir...
we can't leave
our animals here to die.
Besides, how could we build
our future without our animals?
All right.
Chief O'Brien,
transport this group
directly to Cargo Hold 7
and beam the remaining
refugees from the planet
directly to that hold.
Yes, sir.
Right, lads, everybody back
onto the infernal machine.
All right, everybody up here.
Uh, Captain, Captain.
'Twas very good of you, sir
to rescue us
from our troubles.
My pleasure.
Yes. Uh, sir.
You must be
worth quite a bit
to own a fine
ship like this.
I don't own
the Enterprise.
I command her.
Oh, whatever.
Ah, sir, would you happen
to be married?
No. Why?
No?
Well, you see, sir,
I have a daughter.
Felicitations.
Would you be
interested, sir?
No.
You're quite sure?
Quite sure.
Um, he's quite sure.
What's the total?
Two hundred
and twenty-three.
Count on two more
in the next few days.
Set course for
the nearest Starbase.
You know, they were
anachronistic in 2123.
It will be interesting
to see how they cope.
They'll learn and adapt.
If Danilo Odell
is any indication
they'll be running this place
inside of a week.
( alarm sounding )
Lieutenant Worf here, report.
MAN:
Fire in Cargo Hold 7.
The Bringloidi.
What have they done
to my ship now?
Keep the area clear.
Report.
The fire has
been contained.
No damage.
Unseal the doors.
My God, Picard, the place
is a bloody deathtrap.
Lightening bolts falling
from the ceiling.
DANILO:
What the hell was that thing?
WORF:
Automated fire system.
A force field
contains the flame
until the remaining
oxygen has been consumed.
Ah, wh-wh-what if I'd
been under that thing?
You would have been
standing in the fire.
Yeah, well, leaving that aside
for the moment--
I mean, what would have
happened to me?
You would have
suffocated and died.
Ah, sweet mercy.
Oh, there you are.
Your hospitality
leaves a hell of a
lot to be desired.
You don't offer us
a bite or a sup
and when we build a fire
to cook a little something
the whole
place goes mad.
I, um...
My apologies.
I was unaware
that you had not been
instructed in the use
of the food
dispensers.
And what are you staring at?
Have you never
seen a woman before?
I thought I had.
DANILO:
Uh, Commander.
May I present my
daughter, Brenna Odell.
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
You may have all
the time in the world
but I have dozens of
frightened and hungry
children and women
to look after.
And what about the men?
Well, I'm sure they'll
find their comfort
as they always do--
in the bottom of a
mug of home brew.
( chuckling )
Pay no heed, Commander.
She's a fine girl.
She's not usually
as sharp-tongued as that.
BRENNA:
Dado!
Sir?
That's the last
thing I expected.
Sometimes, Number One
you just have to...
bow to the absurd.
Ah, Captain.
Captain, sir.
How did the ship
sense the fire?
Uh, well,
the ship's computers...
Com-pu-ter?
The ship's computers sense
a localized increase...
BRENNA:
Men, always talking
when there's work to be done.
And shouldn't you
be flying this ship
or whatever it is you do?
Shh.
Sir, I think I'll stay
and give her some help.
That isn't necessary.
The ship will clean itself.
Well, good for the bloody ship.
Tell me,
Commander Riker
where does a girl go
to wash her feet on this ship?
As the First Officer
I feel it's
my responsibility
to show you
all the amenities.
She is very much
like a Klingon woman.
Uh, Captain,
just one other thing.
It slipped my mind
in all the hustle and bustle.
The point,
Mr. Odell?
Yes, well, in all your travels
have you heard anything
from the other colony?
The other colony?
Captain's log, supplemental.
A review of stellar charts
has revealed a Class-M planet
only half a light year
from the Bringloid system.
I'm proceeding on the premise
that it was the destination
of the colony
which possessed the more
sophisticated equipment.
William Riker,
you're a mess.
Oh, you don't have to do that.
And if I don't,
who will?
I can see why your father
wants to marry you off.
Oh, and why is that?
So he can have a pipe
and a mug of beer in peace.
You've shown me so many
wonders on your great ship
but there's still one thing
you haven't shown me.
What's that?
I'm still waiting
to wash my feet.
Right behind that door.
William, is something wrong?
What do
you mean?
Do you not like girls?
Of course I do.
Oh, is there a special technique
to this foot washing?
You generally
start at the top
and work
your way down.
I think I can handle that.
I was hoping you might.
( people talking, sheep baaing)
WORF:
You sent for me?
Ah, yes, yes.
Now, we're brewing poteen
but we need to find
a way to heat it
without this bloody ship firing
bloody lightening bolts at us.
You can obtain
spirituous liquors
from the food dispensers.
Huh-uh, oh, no, no.
It's not that synthehol bilge
that O'Brien offered me, is it?
No.
If you wish
it can be real alcohol.
Good.
With all the deleterious
effects intact.
As it should be.
You see, lad
every moment of pleasure in life
has to be purchased
by an equal moment of pain.
Whiskey.
Terrible.
It has no bite.
Chech'tluth.
( wheezing )
Now that's what I call
a wee drop of the creature.
Father!
Remember what I said
about the moment of pain?
Well, 'tis about to begin.
( wheezing ):
Hello, my darling.
Oh, "my darling," is it?
I might
have known.
Are you drunk yet
or can you talk with Dr. Pulaski
about the children?
What about them?
She wants to send them to school
with the ship's children.
What do you think?
I think it's a good idea.
So go handle it.
And I'm sure there's something
you can be doing with your time.
And as for you...
What?
Why did you have to tell them
this magic wall
can give them more
than meat and potatoes?
Now we'll never get
a lick of work out of them.
Madam, have you ever considered
a career
in security?
If it's anything like
baby-sitting, I'm an authority.
( women laughing )
Captain's log, supplemental.
We are approaching
the Class-M planet
where we hope to find
the other colonists.
Signal from the planet, Captain.
On screen.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise
representing the United
Federation of Planets.
This is wonderful.
Welcome, Captain.
I'm Wilson Granger
Prime Minister of Mariposa.
No doubt, a descendant
of Captain Walter Granger.
Not quite a descendant.
We feared Earth had suffered
some catastrophe
when no one came back
to check on us.
I'm afraid the truth is,
you got lost in the bureaucracy.
But despite the lateness
of our arrival
we're here now,
and we're eager to renew ties.
Splendid.
Please come down and allow us
to extend our hospitality
to you and your crew.
Thank you.
Form an away team, Number One.
I would urge caution.
Caution? What's wrong?
He's hiding something.
We'll check it out.
Mr. Worf.
Dr. Pulaski, join us
in Transporter Room 3
for an away detail.
Welcome to Mariposa.
I am Victor Granger,
Minister of Health.
Commander
William Riker
Dr. Pulaski,
Lieutenant Worf.
A pleasure.
I'll escort you
to the Prime Minister.
This way, please.
Twin brothers?
GRANGER:
Your arrival really
is serendipitous.
PULASKI:
Oh, how so?
well, uh, perhaps I'll let
the Prime Minister explain that.
Triplets?
Worf, there is something
damn odd going on here.
Quadruplets.
Doctor, is your title
scientific or medical?
Medical.
Ah, excellent.
Is there some
medical problem we
should know about?
I think it best
if the, uh...
Prime Minister
explains that.
Somehow, I thought
you might.
Yes, excuse me.
Gentlemen?
Please follow me.
( whirring softly )
This way please.
Doctor?
Welcome to Mariposa.
Dr. Katherine Pulaski.
This is my Chief of Staff,
Elizabeth Vallis.
Tell me, is your
entire population
made up of clones,
Prime Minister?
Clones?
Clones.
Captain's log, supplemental.
Prime Minister Granger
has requested an urgent meeting
to discuss the future
of the Mariposan colony.
I've invited him
to the Enterprise.
Captain, we need your help.
300 years ago,
during our landing on Mariposa
the skin of our ship
was breached.
Only five of the colonists
survived.
The progenitors weren't willing
to just give up and die
and they were scientists...
PICARD:
So they used their expertise
and turned to cloning.
Yes, we had no other option.
Two women and three men
represented
an insufficient gene pool
from which to build a society.
Well, how did
you suppress
the natural sexual drive?
Drugs?
Punitive laws?
In the beginning,
a little bit of each.
Now, after 300 years
the entire concept
of sexual reproduction
is a little repugnant to us.
How did you
overcome
the problem
of replicative fading?
We haven't.
You have got a problem.
Wait, I don't understand
"replicative fading."
Each time you clone,
you're making a copy of a copy.
Subtle errors creep
into the chromosomes
and eventually you end up
with a non-viable clone.
How can we help you?
We need an infusion
of fresh DNA.
I was hoping
that you would be willing
to share some
tissue samples.
You want to clone us?
Yes.
No way.
Not me.
But how could you possibly
be harmed?
It's not a question of harm.
One William Riker is unique,
perhaps even special
but a hundred of him,
a thousand of him
diminishes me
in ways I can't even imagine.
You would be
preserving yourself.
Human beings have other ways
of doing that.
We have children.
I think you will find
that attitude prevalent
among all
the Enterprise people.
I see.
Well, if you are not willing
to share your DNA
will you at least
send some people
to repair
our malfunctioning equipment?
Yes, of course.
Number One,
put a technical team together.
Let's get these repairs
underway.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant La Forge
prepare a technical
support away team.
Meet me in
Transporter Room 3.
Captain, with your permission
I would like to return
to the planet.
It could be my last opportunity
to study replicative fading.
With your permission, of course,
Mr. Prime Minister.
You would be
most welcome.
Perhaps you will
find a solution that
we have overlooked.
Well, I appreciate
the compliment
but I don't think
that's very likely.
And repairing that equipment
will certainly not
solve your problems.
What other solution
do we have?
Doctor, remember, there
are only five of us.
Captain's log, supplemental.
Commander Riker and Dr. Pulaski
have returned to Mariposa
with a team
of Enterprise technicians.
The repairs are
almost complete.
I wish there was
something more
we could do.
Are you sure
you won't reconsider?
About the cloning?
Yes.
Out of the
question.
Excuse me, sir,
I was, uh...
I was looking
for Commander Riker.
I'm afraid I haven't seen him.
Dr. Pulaski?
Sorry, I can't help you.
Well, I guess
I'll just have to hunt for them.
Sorry to disturb you.
Hey, so what happened to
you two down on Mariposa?
Is everything all right?
Is there any reason
it shouldn't be?
Yeah, every time I
asked where you were
some clone
lied to me.
Lied to you?
Commander, with this, I can see
better than your average person.
Now, when someone lies
there are certain
physiological manifestations--
variations in
blush response
pupil dilation,
pulse, breath rate.
Doesn't always work with aliens,
but humans--
I got them nailed.
The clones lied
about our whereabouts?
Mm-hmm.
I don't remember
anything happening.
I was working
in their medical facility
and got a call to report
to Granger's office.
I ran into Will
on the way and...
Now, wait a minute.
Granger said that he hadn't seen
either one of you.
Now, did you make it
to his office?
I think...
I don't remember.
So, what's the
prognosis, Doc?
Geordi, you'll be
pleased to know
that you're not missing
any epithelial cells.
Great.
Will and I, however are.
Meaning?
Although you can clone
from any cell in the body
the cells lining the stomach
are the best choice
because they're relatively
undifferentiated.
LA FORGE:
Where you going?
To their cloning lab.
GRANGER:
Stop!
Murderers.
Like hell.
You're a damn thief.
Gentlemen, please.
What else
could we do?
We asked for your help
and you refused us.
We're desperate!
Desperate!
And that gave you the right
to assault us?
To rob us at...
We have the right to survive.
Doctor, how desperate
is the colony's situation?
Well, they've got
two or three generations
and then the fading
will be terminal.
They're among
the walking dead now.
They just haven't been buried.
RIKER:
I want the cloning
equipment inspected.
Who knows how many other
tissue samples were stolen.
We certainly have a right
to exercise control
over our own bodies.
You'll get no argument from me.
I know the Mariposan culture
seems alien
even frightening
but, really,
we do have much in common.
They're human beings
fighting for survival.
Would we do any less?
Are you saying
we should give them
the DNA samples they require?
That's just postponing
the inevitable.
If they get an infusion
of fresh DNA, in 15 generations
they'll just go back
to the same problems.
Cloning isn't the answer.
What they need
is breeding stock.
The Bringloidi.
Yes.
They have the energy
and drive
and the clones possess
the emotional maturity
and the technical knowledge.
They started out together.
It seems only fitting
they should end up together.
It's a match made in heaven.
Unfortunately, it will have
to be a shotgun wedding.
I'm sorry, Captain,
it's out of the question.
You're trying to dump
your problems on us.
We have problems
of our own.
Don't you understand?
The Bringloidi can help you.
Look at him.
How could we ever integrate that
into our society?
You're no prize
yourself.
Primitive,
hostile, disruptive.
It would require
enormous effort
to even educate them.
Oh, forget it,
Captain Picard.
I'm not going to come in here
with my hat in my hand
begging charity
from this blatherskite.
Now stop!
I will not allow
posturing and bigotry
to destroy this meeting.
Now, please, sit down.
Now, Commander Riker
has asked
that your laboratories
be inspected
for stolen
tissue samples
and I understand
his concern.
We may have to transport
all your equipment here
to the Enterprise.
I see.
When reason fails,
you'll resort to blackmail.
Fine, destroy yourselves.
PULASKI:
It's not so bad, Captain.
In 50 years, we'll have
a new Class-M planet
complete with cities
and ready for colonization.
You see, the end is closer
than you like to think.
I don't know.
There are so many difficulties.
Look, man...
we are decent,
hard-working people.
We're willing to learn.
They're so different.
It is the differences
that have made us strong.
For 300 years, we have denied
the carnal side of our nature.
How can we learn
to put that aside?
Well...
you, you, you put
a young couple together
and you let nature
take its course.
Now, if this is going to work
you're going to have
to alter your society, too.
Monogamous marriage
will not be possible
for several generations.
I don't quite understand.
30 couples are enough to create
a viable genetic base
but the broader the base
the healthier,
and the safer the society.
So, it would be best
if each woman--
Bringloidi
and Mariposan--
had at least
three children
by three
different men.
I... I think I could
handle that, yes.
Oh, God, it's so...
Frightening?
Repugnant.
So it's a done deal?
And here is
my hand on it.
Ho-ho-ho!
Right, well, now let's go
and stake out
my three women.
Send in the clones.
I must be out of my mind.
Starfleet will probably
agree with you.
Ah, excuse me,
sir, Captain.
Thank you, sir.
Brenna... Brenna....
Hmm?
A word.
( men laughing )
Isn't that just
like a man!
You make these
grandiose decisions
but you never stop to
consider the poor women.
Miss Odell, I...
You men draw a mug, and
solve all the problems
of the world while
the beer goes down
but when it comes
to the practical matters
it always falls to the women
to make your grand dreams
come true.
Miss Odell, you were the one
who wanted a new home.
But I don't know
if I want to be Eve.
It's your choice.
If you wish, you can stay
on the Enterprise.
We will drop you off
at a Starbase.
Then you can go where you wish.
Leave my dad?
If this is going to work
these people will need
your strength.
Your guidance.
Oh, damn.
What does he do again?
Prime Minister.
Sounds important.
Oh, it is.
Sounds like
he might have
more than two coins
to rub together.
Three husbands?
Uh-huh.