Captain's log,
Stardate 42859.2.
We are in orbit
around Antede 3
awaiting the arrival
of two dignitaries.
Our mission is
to escort them
to a conference
on planet Pacifica
where they will be given
the opportunity
to join the Federation.
I thought you might find
this interesting, Mr. Crusher.
Few humans have seen
an Antedian in the flesh.
Welcome.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard
captain of
the Enterprise.
Are they
all right, sir?
Yes.
This is their
preferred way
of space travel.
PULASKI:
Their physical condition
is good enough,
considering
the circumstances.
It is a self-induced
catatonic state--
their way of dealing
with the trauma
of spaceflight.
Will we try
to revive them?
No. Not until we reach
the Pacifica conference
three days
from now.
Doctor, have you prepared
a sick bay facility
to accommodate
our guests?
Well as soon as I can make
some adjustments.
Their physiology
is unusual.
You can store them
for a few hours?
Sure, I'll have them
kept here out of the way.
Mr. Worf,
provide security.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
What's in that
container?
Vermicula.
It's their food.
When they come out of stasis,
they'll be very hungry.
They eat this?
In great quantities.
What a handsome race.
So what did you think
of the Antedians, Wesley?
They are... rather
strange looking, Commander.
Judging a being by its
physical appearance
is the last major
human prejudice, Wesley.
Point is well taken,
Mr. Data.
I'm sure that
to the Antedians,
we are equally
unattractive.
Captain,
we are being hailed
by a small transport vessel,
just coming into range.
Oh, my God.
What's the problem?
What's she doing here?
WESLEY:
On screen, Captain.
Starship Enterprise,
come in.
RIKER:
We have you on viewer, pilot.
Enterprise,
I have a passenger.
A V.I.P. passenger
who I--
Oh, let me talk
to them.
I'm sure I'm more
articulate than that.
Mother.
DATA:
Captain,
we are receiving
Starfleet orders
granting a Lwaxana...
Lwaxana Troi!
A daughter of
the Fifth House,
holder of the
Sacred Chalice of Riix,
heir to the Holy Rings
of Betazed.
...full ambassadorial
status, sir.
It looks like it's back
into that dress uniform, sir.
And yours as well,
Commander.
She is listed
as representing
the Betazed government
at the conference.
Mother, please,
don't do this to me.
LWAXANA:
Do what to you,
little one?
Oh! Jean-Luc,
what naughty
thoughts.
But how wonderful you still
think of me like that.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
It's so like my mother
to do the unexpected.
Well, it will
be... pleasant
to have her as a guest
of the Enterprise again.
Energize.
Legs!
Where are the legs?
Where they belong, Mother,
right under you.
Oh, I hate that.
I will never completely trust
this device, Jean-Luc.
Captain Picard, Mother.
( startled cry )
Explain to her.
I'm sorry they startled
you Mrs. Troi.
They're Antedian
delegates.
They're being stored
here temporarily.
Delegates?
Last time I saw
something like that,
it was being served
on a plate.
Darling.
Ah.
LWAXANA:
Well, well, well.
And you Jean-Luc,
I wasn't aware you had
such handsome legs.
My valet is waiting.
You may beam him
aboard now.
You remember Mr. Homn,
of course.
It would be hard
to forget Mr. Homn.
I've retained
his services despite
the outlandishly
lustful thoughts
he spews
in my direction.
You can put
that down, Homn.
We can't deny the captain
the honor
of carrying
my belongings.
I will not interfere with
Mr. Homn's duties this time.
Oh, now,
that's not what
you're really thinking,
Jean-Luc.
You forget,
I'm a telepath.
Mrs. Troi, since this
is obviously
significant to you...
I'll--
I'll carry it.
Just down this corridor.
LWAXANA:
He has nice legs too,
little one.
Is he still yours?
Humans no longer own
each other that way, Mother.
Really?
That's a custom we may
have to introduce again.
Thank you.
Glad to help.
Well, I trust you will
be comfortable here.
If you will
excuse me...
Uh, I am serving
a Betazoid
dinner of greeting
tonight, Captain.
It is an ambassadorial
function.
It sounds delightful.
He's a fine man.
Solid, he's reliable.
He's a little bit
on the stuffy side
but, uh, all in all,
he's not that bad.
I can't believe you,
Mother.
You sound like you're
sizing up a commodity.
But that's exactly
what men are,
darling,
especially human men.
Was your father ever
unhappy with me?
No.
He worshipped you.
But I don't think
I'll ever learn
to see men
the way you do.
You will as
you mature, darling.
And the men in your life
are going to bless you for it.
You're so beautiful.
And she actually complimented
Captain Picard on his legs?
I would have
thought a telepath
would be more
discreet, sir.
RIKER:
Exactly the opposite.
She knows what's on your mind
and she lets you know
what's on hers.
(laughing)
PICARD: Gentlemen...
I think we must not
lose sight of the fact
that we are talking
about someone
who has been granted
ambassadorial rank,
even though
she may appear...
somewhat eccentric.
Lwaxana Troi must
be treated with
the appropriate respect.
Is that understood?
Picard to Pulaski.
Yes, Captain?
When did you last look in
on the Antedian guests?
Doing so right now,
Captain.
Are they still catatonic?
Status of the beings
is unchanged.
Pulse, still steady.
Respiration...
normal for them.
Understood.
Keep me informed.
Picard out.
I'll be
in my quarters.
It will be a dress uniform
dinner, gentlemen.
Sir?
To which dinner was
the captain referring, sir?
Nothing I've been invited to.
Any of you?
Very interesting.
Doctor?
You're not attending
the dinner
with the rest
of us this evening?
I've already eaten,
but thanks, Captain.
I seem to be
a little early.
I'm sure the others
will be here soon.
The other officers--
Commander Riker,
Counselor Troi?
Hello, Jean-Luc.
So glad you could come.
A toast,
to Earth men
who, despite their
many faults,
have that
unique ability
to charm women
of all races
in all corners
of the galaxy.
Speaking on behalf
of men of Earth,
which is indeed
an awesome responsibility,
I thank you.
I know what you're
thinking, Captain.
You do?
You're wondering
whether I'm seeing
any other man...
on a serious basis.
Well, actually,
I wasn't, uh--
Ah, I wouldn't worry
about it, Jean-Luc.
Competition seems
to bring out
the best in
the human male.
The fact is,
I, um... uh...
I was not expecting
this, uh, this setting.
I had assumed that
my senior bridge officers
would be attending.
You never assume
anything
where Lwaxana Troi
is concerned.
Betazoid women are
full of surprises.
Ah, strange.
I'm not really
very hungry tonight.
I wonder what's made me
lose my appetite.
Any ideas?
( gong chiming )
Of course. You're giving
thanks for your food.
I had forgotten
about that.
I wonder how many other
cultures have similar customs.
Uh, I don't know.
Well, let's find out.
Commander Data?
Yes, Captain.
Mrs. Troi and I are having
a very interesting discussion
about various societies'
ways of giving thanks.
The Betazoids' use of
the chime, for instance.
The use of the chime
is quite unique,
but not at all
dissimilar
to the Ooolans
of Marejaretus 6,
who use two large stones
which are continuously
struck together during
the meal.
Those at the dinner must eat
until the stones are broken.
Or the oligarchy
at Atifs 4,
which requires a young--
Data,
this is fascinating.
Don't you agree,
Mrs. Troi?
Commander, if your
duties permit,
why don't you
join us for dessert?
I'm sure that Mrs. Troi
would much appreciate
the pleasure of your company.
What?
Indeed, sir.
I'm on my way.
Data out.
How could you
possibly think
I would want to share
our special time together
with that-- that--
that robot of yours?
Because of Data's wonderful
after-dinner conversation.
His anecdotes are the stuff
of legends aboard this ship.
So, by using
the square root of pi
and multiplying it by
nine to the third power,
I was able to
accurately calculate
the distance between
the Omicron system
and the Crab Nebula.
Oh! Ah.
Fascinating, Data.
Absolutely fascinating.
I'm sure Mrs. Troi
would love to hear
the one about
the anomalous chemical
composition of,
um, brown
dwarf stars.
Not really.
Yes, Captain...
that is a particularly
spellbinding subject.
In most stars,
the rare-earth
element europium
is enriched relative to
samarium and gadolinium.
That so?
It is. However--
Your mother seems quite
an interesting woman, Deanna.
Hmm, perhaps I should
tell you something
about my mother's
condition at this time.
"Condition
at this time"?
It's something that occurs
to Betazed females
as they enter mid-life.
We call it "the phase."
Mid-life, as in a human
female's menopause?
Similar.
It's only at mid-life
that a Betazoid
female becomes...
well, fully sexual,
if you know what I mean.
Yes, I think I do.
I also think
that I saw the captain
on his way
to her quarters.
I wonder if
I shouldn't warn him?
No.
As ship's doctor,
I consider it an
excellent exercise
for his reflexes
and agility.
Doctor!
For staying ahead
of your mother.
Yes.
An animal is always
at its best when hunted.
Or, when hunting.
... and at this point,
the second coorbital satellite
avoids a collision
with the first--
Deanna, darling, thank
the four deities you're here.
I hope I'm not
interrupting.
No, I must, as
a matter of fact,
be getting back
to the bridge.
DATA:
Captain...
perhaps I should remain
and further entertain our guest.
No!
I-- I mean,
I'm sure you're needed on
the bridge as well.
Well, thank you
for, um...
a delicious meal.
We must do this
again sometime.
I know we will.
Well, little one...
the captain is every bit
as charming as your father was.
( gong chiming )
Mmm.
( gong chiming)
( sighing )
Data, you will never know
how much I owe
you for that.
Indeed, Captain?
I know many more
interesting anecdotes, sir.
For example--
Data.
Sir?
Later.
Yes, sir.
Why would you come aboard
at a time like this?
Well I had no choice.
I was going to Pacifica,
you were going
to Pacifica.
Don't be absurd,
Mother.
You knew what
would happen.
What stage is it in?
Oh, I have it completely
under control.
What stage is it in?
Well, far enough along
for me to enjoy it,
little one.
Now I know why you
wore that dress.
Wha--
Don't be ridiculous.
This simple
little dress?
Nothing provocative
about it.
What are we going to do?
Well I'm going to do
the only
honorable thing
there is to do.
And I'd say your captain
has the inside track.
Mother, don't even
think it.
Why not?
He was thinking about it
all through dinner.
I was what?
I tell you,
Deanna...
for a telepath,
your mother's accuracy
leaves much
to be desired.
Actually, her
telepathic prowess
is quite advanced...
except for now.
"Except for now"?
Don't misunderstand me,
Counselor.
Your mother is
a beautiful person.
My mother is beginning
a physiological phase.
It's one that all Betazoid
women must deal with
as they enter
mid-life.
RIKER:
Yes it's something
Troi warned me about
when we first started
to see each other.
A Betazoid woman, when
she goes through this phase...
quadruples
her sex drive.
Or more.
Or more?
You never
told me that.
I didn't want
to frighten you.
She has opted for
the only dignified
option open to her.
Isolation?
She has decided to focus
all her sexual energy
on one male
who will, of course,
eventually become
her husband.
It seems,
Captain, that...
you are the early
favorite.
Congratulations,
sir.
I'm not amused,
Number One.
There must be some way
to convince her
that it's...
quite impossible...
without offending her.
You cannot apply human-style
logic to this, Captain.
A Betazoid woman
in the phase
would be shocked
and deeply resentful
should you spurn
any such advances.
She would take it
personally.
Well, under
the circumstances,
I think it would
be prudent
if I were
to make myself...
less available for
the duration of the journey.
Agreed.
PICARD:
Setting-- San Francisco,
California.
United States of America.
The year-- 1941 A.D.
The office of Dixon Hill,
private investigator.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
You may enter
when ready.
Hi, Dix.
Madeline.
Good to see you again.
You're too much,
Dix.
You make it sound like
you ain't seen me in a year.
( chuckling )
You got two calls.
They're on your desk.
New cases?
Are you kidding?
The last time
we had a new case,
Hitler and Stalin
were bosom buddies.
The landlord came by.
He wants the geetus,
or he wants you out.
The geetus?
The moolah, Dix,
the rent.
And since we're
on the subject,
it's been a month
since I seen anything.
Now, I know
it's been tough
since you got out
of the hospital,
but I got
responsibilities.
Then, I suppose
I had better get a case.
It wouldn't hurt!
( '40s ballad )
Unavailable?
Ship's business?
You mean ship's business
takes precedence over me?
I'm afraid so,
Mother.
Oh.
Well...
he was too old
for me, anyway.
Homn!
Perhaps we should consider
my alternate plan.
DEANNA:
Alternate plan?
Oh, you worry too much,
little one.
Your mother has the
situation well in hand.
There's a gentleman here
to see you, Mr. Hill.
And he doesn't look
like a client.
Hill, the name
is Slade Bender.
Excuse me.
( turns off music )
what can I do for you,
Mr. Bender?
It's about Alva.
You'll have to be
a little more precise.
Okay, you want
to play stupid.
That's jake with me.
A week ago,
a man came in here.
He wanted you to find
his girlfriend, name's Alva.
Did I find her?
You know, you're getting
on my nerves.
You found her, all right,
face down in the river.
Oh, I'm sorry
to hear that.
Yeah, yeah, we're all
broken up about it.
Especially the boyfriend,
who has been indicted
for murder.
And, what are
you here to do,
ask for a refund?
Nah, I'm here
to kill you.
Computer,
freeze program!
Computer, this isn't
what I wanted at all.
( sighing )
It's much too violent.
I'm here to relax,
not to dodge bullets.
Reconfigure.
COMPUTER:
Please define.
Um, more... ambience.
Less substance.
Do you wish to leave
the holodeck and reenter,
or continue
from this point?
No, I will continue.
Program complete.
You may continue.
MADELINE:
There's a gentleman
here to see you, Mr. Hill.
Thank you, Madeline.
You a private dick?
That's what it
says on my door.
Is that supposed
to be funny?
Because if it is...
you got
to know that...
I ain't in the mood
for funny.
Now I came here
on serious business.
There's a job I want you
to do for me.
Computer,
freeze program.
Clear!
Computer, this
still isn't right.
One kind of violence has
been substituted for another.
Reconfigure.
You may continue.
Thank you.
You're through ducking me,
Hill!
Computer,
freeze program!
Variations
on a theme.
Computer,
perhaps I am not
clearly defining
my intent.
The flexibility of the program
is limited
to the parameters
of the Dixon Hill novels.
Yes, of course.
Even in this state,
they possess
a certain dignity.
A graceful countenance.
If you say so,
Lieutenant.
I see.
Is this how you felt
when you first saw me?
Well, maybe at first,
a little.
But now that I've seen
more Klingons,
I've come
to think you're--
you're handsome,
for a Klingon.
That didn't quite come out
the way I meant, sir.
( gasping )
LWAXANA:
I still say they'd look
better in sauce.
When will the good
captain revive them?
Not until we reach
Pacifica, ma'am.
Oh.
You seem
a fine boy.
One day you'll grow up
to be a big, strong man.
But, I'm afraid I cannot afford
to wait for you to mature.
Now that's
more like it.
Your thoughts,
they're primal, savage...
I like that in a man.
I am not a man.
Oh, which is
in your favor,
men so often being
irrational and egotistical.
But,
unfortunately,
I've grown accustomed
to human companionship.
Pity.
You'd have made
a fine choice.
Well, who is next,
Mr. Homn?
Ah, yes.
Well, let's to it.
I'm not getting
any younger.
What was that
all about?
So, Madeline,
I'll see you later.
Activate program.
Leaving, Dix?
Uh-huh.
You're not going
to Rex's bar, are you?
Rex's bar.
Why do you ask?
It's one of the messages
I left on your desk.
Well, that sounds like
an excellent idea.
Would you care
to join me?
Me? Have a drink
with you?
Why not?
There ain't no
"why not" about it.
It's just that this is
the first time you ever asked.
Is that a problem?
Not for me.
But you better
take this.
Why?
Because if we're
going to Rex's bar,
you're gonna
need it.
( conversational chatter,
laughter )
Hey, Dix, what do you know
and what do you say?
See this?
Germany's getting ready
to invade England.
Who's gonna stop 'em?
Somebody better.
As long as it isn't us.
The last thing America
needs to do
is fight in another
world war.
Actually, the second world war,
although disastrous,
did end with the United States
taking its place
as a dominant world power
and cultural influence
in the second half of
the 20th century.
Additionally,
that war was a catalyst
of technological
advancement.
Developments in rocketry
and fission
resonate on into
the 24th century.
I don't know if I should
pour you one, Dix.
Sounds like you got
a snootful already.
What's this?
The usual.
Uh-huh. Ah, yes,
now let me see.
That would be, uh,
scotch, neat.
What else?
And for the lady?
Rye and ginger.
Money.
I keep forgetting
the need to carry money.
I must remember not to let
this happen again.
Right, I don't mind you
being on the cuff,
but you're up the sleeve
halfway to my collar.
Is that why you wanted
to see me, about my bar bill?
No, it's on account
of... Jimmy Cuzzo.
Jimmy Cuzzo--
I know that name.
He's why I gave you
the gun.
What was the name of
that case he was involved in?
The Parrot's Claw.
MADELINE:
Geez, Dix.
Cuzzo is the guy who
iced Marty O'farron.
They never would've nailed him
if it hadn't been for you.
Your testimony
got him "arranged."
Yeah.
Yours and mine.
So you brought me here
because you didn't want
to face him alone.
I don't want
to face him at all.
I'm hoping that
seeing us together
will slow him up
long enough
to get some things
straight.
And if it doesn't?
Then you just have
to kill him.
Bridge, this is
Dr. Pulaski.
We've just completed
the transfer.
The Antedians
are now in sick bay.
Acknowledged,
Doctor.
Mother, what are you
doing here?
You can't just
stroll onto the bridge
whenever you feel
like it.
I didn't just
stroll on, dear.
I took that "turbotube,"
or whatever you call it.
Uh, the captain's
not here?
Um, he is busy
elsewhere, ma'am.
Oh, well...
I have other
interests as well.
You're scheming
something, Mother.
Don't try to fool me,
I can tell.
You're always so
melodramatic, little one.
I'm not scheming,
I'm deciding.
Mother, not him.
And why not him?
He's adorable.
Pulaski to bridge.
Riker here.
The Antedians
are coming around.
They are currently in the early
stages of posthibernation.
How long until
they're fully conscious?
I guess it to be
a matter of hours now.
Very well, I'll
inform the captain.
If you'll
excuse me, ma'am.
You're going
to see the captain?
But I thought he was tied up
on ship's business.
In a manner
of speaking, he is.
I'm not going to be
disturbing him.
I'll just give him
the message.
Oh.
Excellent timing.
Then you may also
inform him about us.
Us ?
You don't mind
if I let our ship's crew
know first, do you, William?
Uh, friends,
dear friends...
You are all invited
to a prestigious occasion
on the planet Pacifica.
No.
There...
on the shores
of the western sea,
in a traditional
Betazoid ceremony,
your Commander Riker
and I will be joined
in the union
of matrimony.
Married?
Until death
us do part.
Mrs. Troi, I don't know
how to tell you this--
Oh, I know how
you feel, dear.
You're overwhelmed
with excitement.
Oh, believe me,
I understand.
We'll talk about
the details later.
Right now, there are
preparations to be made.
Why did you stop me?
Somebody needs
to set her straight.
I think I'll leave that
to the Captain.
Coward.
Commander...
are you planning
on going into the holodeck?
I thought I might.
Would you like to join me?
Could you postpone our departure
for just five minutes, sir?
No problem.
You said you had
responsibilities.
What exactly
did you mean?
You know about
my mother's cousin.
The girl from San Antonio
I told you about?
( gasping )
Jimmy.
( sighing )
I'm as jumpy
as Haircut Lapinski
trying to land
on a fraction.
Sorry to bother you,
Captain.
Captain?
Call me Dix.
Sorry to bother you,
Dix,
But our two passengers
have awakened.
Oh, then it's time
for me to go.
What about Jimmy Cuzzo?
You can't leave Rex
to face him alone.
I'll be back before
Jimmy Cuzzo arrives.
I guarantee,
it will be taken care of.
Just relax.
Your friends have time
for one drink,
haven't they, Dix?
Oh, yes, of course.
One more round.
These are
my associates.
This is, uh, "Nails,"
from Chicago,
and this is, uh...
Carlos.
From South America.
This is Madeline,
my secretary.
And I want you
to meet Rex...
you know, I don't think
I ever heard your last name.
Hmm. Don't think
I have one.
Just Rex,
that's all.
So fellas, tell me
your troubles.
Well troubles,
we've got some, Captain.
It seems that a certain woman,
both wealthy and beautiful,
now thinks that she is
going to marry me.
REX:
She's got looks
and bucks?
Sounds like you've got
yourself one heck of a deal.
Oh, my fiance just has
to see how I look in this.
Come along, Homn.
Hello, uh...
computer?
Is Commander Riker
still on the bridge?
Negative. Riker is currently
in Holodeck 3.
Uh, um, holodeck?
Uh, where is that?
Follow the com-panel lights.
They will lead you there.
Com--
Oh. Oh!
Oh!
Good God, what's that?
I bet that's the broad
with the big bucks.
Hey come on over here,
darling.
I've got the best
stool in the house
saved for you.
So this is where you've
been hiding, Jean-Luc.
I'm surprised you let
this part
of the ship
get this dirty.
Oh, relax,
Commander.
You've been making your
true feelings quite clear.
Obviously, you feel
unable to handle me.
Anyway, why would
a beautiful
high-class lady
like yourself
want to hook up
with a mug like that?
You're too good for him
if you ask me.
You are a very
interesting person.
You're not so bad
yourself.
In fact, you're as much class
as this joint's ever seen.
Here.
On the house.
It's French...
well, almost.
This is the most
remarkable man.
I've never met anyone
like him.
I don't suppose
you have.
He's strong.
I get no thoughts
from him at all, nothing.
Well I've never known
a man so able
to keep his true
feelings completely hidden.
That's because--
No man has ever...
been such a mystery to me.
I usually know their thoughts
before they do.
But not with me, huh?
No.
And I never realized
how erotic that could be.
Um... carry my beverage
to that table.
We have some things
to discuss.
Should we tell her?
( sighing )
I think it would be
only fair...
but let's
allow her the moment.
(shouting )
Worf, the vermicula.
( shouting )
Pulaski to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, doctor.
Our passengers are
on their... feet.
Understood.
We better get
to the bridge.
What's their condition?
Hungry.
Would you like to be shown
to your rooms?
Are you coming,
Mrs. Troi?
Uh, not just yet.
Tell William that
I'm sorry,
but Rex and I are
getting married.
Mrs. Troi, your government
expects me
to deliver you to
the conference on time,
and that's what I intend
to do.
Pity.
Duty calls,
darling.
But I'll be back
for you later.
PICARD:
Mrs. Troi,
there is something
you ought to know
about Rex.
Oh?
Imagine, allowing me
to go on like that
with that man
who doesn't even exist.
But you always say you
like surprises, Mother.
Hmm.
Why are they still here?
We thought since you were
going to the same conference,
you might like to beam down
with the other delegates.
Oh, they're not delegates,
those two are assassins.
That is an outrage!
Lies!
We demand you transport us
at once.
Don't bother
to deny it.
Your minds are
so unsophisticated,
I can read your thoughts
in my sleep.
Oh, their robes
are lined with ultritium.
Highly explosive,
virtually undetectable
by your transporter.
She is correct, sir.
I am detecting large
amounts of ultritium.
Well, of course you are.
They were planning
on blowing up
the entire conference.
Mr. Worf,
take them to level 5.
Disarm them.
Hold them for questioning.
Aye, sir.
Ah, well, I didn't
find a mate,
but I did save
the conference,
as well as
your reputations.
All in a day's work,
I suppose.
Good-bye, Mrs. Troi...
and, thank you.
PICARD:
Energize, Chief O'Brien.
Jean-Luc...
shame on you for
thinking such a thing.