Looking good.
I'll go five.
Five here.
And five more.
I believe the wiser course
of action here is to bend.
You mean fold, Data.
That is correct.
Fold: to bend,
to make compact,
or to capitulate.
I raise 50.
I do not believe
Lieutenant Worf
understands
all the nuances
of this betting procedure.
I wouldn't be
so quick to judge, Data.
His pile's a lot bigger
than yours.
Than any of ours.
The cards have been favoring
the Lieutenant,
but that is the result
of random chance.
Therefore,
a temporary situation.
You hope.
Talk or play-- not both.
50, right?
50 is the bet.
What's the matter?
Feet getting cold?
My cards are getting cold.
Here you go.
I'm glad you stayed in.
I need the chips.
Talk, talk, talk.
Okay, here's the action.
Fifty.
And another 50.
Ouch.
Fold, fold, fold.
Your 50, and 50 more.
Love to play, but not
with these cards.
Looks like
it's just us, handsome.
I'll see you.
( La Forge whistles )
Beats my straight.
The iceman
wins again.
You took my last chip.
You could at least
smile, Worf.
Smiling would break
his concentration.
Your deal.
Geordi?
The game is seven-card stud.
After the queen,
one-eyed jacks
and low card
in the hole are wild.
Wait a minute, let me
write this down.
I open with 50.
CREWMAN:
Bridge to Commander Riker.
We're receiving
a class 11 emergency signal
from Starfleet Command.
On my way.
50?
You were bluffing.
Klingons never bluff.
Yeah, right.
Mr. Data?
Emergency signal
reads as follows--
"Enterprise to divert
to coordinates 4-2-3
"by 1-1-2 by
5-1 immediately.
Further orders
forthcoming."
That's it?
What's the emergency?
The message did not
elaborate, sir.
You'd think they'd
at least give us a hint.
CLANCY:
Course laid in, Captain.
Warp 8.
Whenever Starfleet
gets enigmatic,
I know we're about
to face a challenge.
Engage.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Our destination is a point
near the Boradis system.
That area was colonized
recently, as I recall.
The first Federation outpost
was established 34 years ago
on Boradis III.
Since then,
the Federation has colonized
several planets in that sector.
Yet, we are not headed
for a specific colony.
The coordinates given are
outside the Boradis system.
Any problems reported
in that area?
DATA:
None, sir.
What the devil is going on?
WORF:
Captain.
Starfleet Command is hailing us.
About time.
On screen.
Greetings, Captain Picard.
My compliments, Admiral Gromek.
Captain, you will soon be joined
by a Federation special emissary
from Starbase 153.
We are now transmitting
the specifics.
We are receiving, sir.
GROMEK: The rendezvous
will be a bit tricky,
so it is imperative
that you reach the intercept
point on schedule.
Understood. And the mission?
The envoy will
fill you in.
You are to cooperate fully.
Admiral, can you give me
any details?
Negative.
Admiral, it's a little
difficult to prepare
for a mission
I know nothing about.
I sympathize, Jean-Luc.
But Starfleet Command considers
this a top security matter.
Once the envoy has briefed you,
I think you will understand
our caution.
Gromek out.
Data, what ship is
transporting the envoy?
DATA: Apparently, there were
no starships available
on Starbase 153.
The envoy is aboard
a class-8 probe.
A class-8 probe is
just over two meters long.
Yes, that's true,
Number One.
But if the transmitters
and the sensors were removed
and a life-support
system installed,
there would be just enough
room for one person.
And it is designed
to travel at warp 9.
DATA: By sending the
probe to meet us
rather than diverting
the Enterprise,
they are saving us 6.1 hours.
Obviously, Starfleet feels
that time is of the essence.
But still, to seal someone
inside a class-8 probe
and launch it off,
that's a hell of a way
to transport a Federation
dignitary.
Coming to 3-1, mark 1-1-3.
We are on a course
precisely parallel
to the probe, sir.
Increase speed
to warp 8.9.
8.9, aye.
Full sensors aft.
Scanning.
Data, if we
project our course
beyond the rendezvous
coordinates,
what lies ahead?
As far as I can determine,
sir, very little.
There are four colonies
in the Boradis system
as well as nine other outposts
scattered throughout the sector.
I have it, sir.
Bearing 0-5, mark 2-3-1.
Velocity, warp 9.
I see it.
Adjust speed
to intercept.
Probe is coming up
to starboard.
Range 8,200.
Tractor beam ready.
Mr. La Forge?
Transporter ready, Captain.
Range now... 7,500.
Steady as she goes.
Probe is standing abeam.
Engage tractor beam.
O'BRIEN: Transporter beam
locked, Captain.
Energize.
Probe aboard, Captain.
Acknowledged.
Number One.
I'll welcome our visitor.
Resume original course
and speed.
Aye, sir.
All yours, Commander.
Hmm.
Something wrong, Doctor?
I'm not sure.
The readings are
quite interesting.
I greet you.
I am K'Ehleyr.
nuqneH qalegneS.
You speak Klingon.
A little.
I'm Commander William Riker.
This is Chief Medical Officer
Katherine Pulaski.
I hope your voyage
wasn't too unpleasant.
Klingons are not supposed
to mind hardship.
Nonetheless, I am delighted
to be out of that damned coffin.
I don't blame you, it's not
most luxurious accommodations
Starfleet has to offer.
Whoever said getting there
was half the fun
never rode in a class-A probe.
How are you feeling?
Your vital signs are rather
atypical for a Klingon.
No doubt
because I am only half Klingon.
Oh?
Yes, my father was Klingon.
My mother was human.
Captain.
Allow me to present Special
Federation Emissary K'Ehleyr.
Welcome aboard.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard.
This is Counselor Troi.
Lieutenant
Commander Data.
And this is Lieutenant...
Worf.
So, this is where
you've been hiding.
I told you we'd meet again.
Aren't you going to greet me?
I have nothing
to say to you.
Haven't changed a bit, hmm?
Well, I missed you, too.
Two days ago,
Starbase 336 received
an automated transmission
from a Klingon ship.
The T'Ong.
That ship was sent out
over 75 years ago.
When the Federation
and the Klingon Empire
were still at war.
The message was directed
to the Klingon High Command.
It said only that the ship
was returning home
and was about to reach
its awakening point.
Which suggests that the crew
had been in cryogenic sleep
for that long journey.
Exactly.
And when this crew is revived?
We'll have a ship
full of Klingons
who think the war
is still going on.
So, our task is to
find the ship
and tell the Klingons
they're no longer at war.
RIKER:
Why us?
Wouldn't a Klingon ship
be a better choice?
A Klingon ship,
the P'Rang, is on its way,
but it's two days behind us.
That may be too late.
Why too late?
RIKER: When the
T'Ong crew awakens,
it will be within
striking range
of several
Federation outposts.
There are 13 colonies
with minimal defenses
in that sector.
Nice, ripe targets
for a Klingon warship.
And you believe you can
convince these Klingons
that the humans
are now their allies?
No, not a chance.
If you ask me, talking will be
a waste of time.
Klingons of that era
were raised
to despise humans.
We'll try diplomacy,
but I promise you,
it won't work.
And then, you'll have
to destroy them.
No.
No?
Captain,
these Klingons are killers.
You'll have no choice.
We shall find another choice.
I want options,
and I want them
before we encounter
the Klingon ship.
Lieutenant...
I'm assigning you
to help the emissary.
Dismissed.
I will escort you
to the guest quarters.
Captain.
Lieutenant?
Sir, I suggest
Commander Riker or Data
would better serve
Special Emissary K'Ehleyr.
Are there any personal reasons
that you don't want
the assignment?
Yes.
Any professional reasons?
No.
I withdraw my request, Captain.
Good.
I didn't know
it was possible
for a human and a Klingon
to produce a child.
Actually, the DNA
is compatible,
with a fair amount of help.
Rather like my parents.
I know exactly
what you mean.
My father was human, and
my mother is a Betazoid.
Really?
It was the other way
around for me.
My mother was human.
You must have grown up
like I did--
trapped
between cultures.
I never felt trapped.
I tried to experience
the richness and diversity
of the two worlds.
Perhaps you got
the best of each.
Myself, I think I got
the worst of each.
Oh, I doubt that.
Oh, yes.
Having my mother's sense
of humor is bad enough.
It's gotten me
into plenty of trouble.
And your Klingon side?
That, I keep under
tight control.
It's like a terrible temper.
It's not something
I want people to see.
Everyone has tempers.
Not like mine.
Sometimes I feel
there's a monster inside of me
fighting to get out.
And it frightens you.
Of course it does.
My Klingon side can be...
terrifying,
even to me.
It gives you strength.
It's a part of you.
That doesn't mean
I have to like it.
You are late.
Sorry.
Had to make
myself beautiful.
I fail to understand why.
Worf, we're alone now.
You don't have to act
like a Klingon glacier.
I don't bite.
Well, that's wrong...
I do bite.
Shall we proceed
with our assigned duties?
You weren't this aloof
six years ago.
Or don't you remember?
There is nothing wrong
with my memory.
Well, there's something
wrong with the rest of you.
You're not even looking at me.
I'm familiar
with your appearance.
And it gives you
no pleasure to see me again.
It isn't as if we tried it
and it didn't work, you know.
You never gave it a chance.
I never?
I mean, as I see it,
we have some...
unfinished business, you and I.
Not as far as I'm concerned.
According to the
library computer,
the Captain of the
T'Ong is K'Temoc.
But there is nothing
regarding the ship's mission.
Probably some
secret military objective.
Perhaps, but we have
no evidence of that.
Why else would there be
no record of the mission?
The records may simply
have been lost.
What does it matter?
Our concern is the present.
The possible threat.
And to contend with that threat,
we need information.
We have all the
information we need.
That is foolish.
Knowing their mission
might help us understand them.
There is nothing to understand.
These are Klingons!
They'll attack.
In their minds,
we're the enemy.
And there's no way we're going
to talk them out of that.
And I do not appreciate
being interrupted.
wasting my time.
We were instructed to
come up with options.
There aren't any,
the assignment's hopeless.
There are always options.
Oh, are there?
Tell me, whatever happened
to that wonderful
Klingon fatalism of yours?
My experiences aboard this ship
have taught me
most problems have
more than one solution.
Starfleet hasn't
improved you one bit.
You're as stubborn as ever.
Are you going to carry out
your duties or aren't you?
All right, I will.
Upon due consideration
of the problem
and careful examination
of all possible options,
my original recommendation
stands.
Meeting adjourned.
( screaming )
( door chime )
( groans )
Come.
You're upset.
Your finely honed
Betazoid sense
tell you that?
Well, that and the table.
( chuckles )
I warned you
about my Klingon half.
May I make a suggestion?
I thank you, Counselor,
but I don't want any counseling.
Actually, I was going to
suggest something else.
Oh?
I find the exercise programs
on the holodeck
rigorous enough to take
my mind off most frustrations.
And it'll keep me
from wrecking the ship.
That, too.
( chuckling )
COMPUTER:
Enter program.
Show me the exercise menu.
Hold.
Calisthenics program
of Lieutenant Worf.
Program complete.
You may enter when ready.
( screeching yowls )
Status, Mr. Data?
Based on the last
assumed position
of the Klingon vessel,
its apparent trajectory,
and our estimates
of their cruising speed,
WORF: I relieve you.
we should be within
scanner range
in 15 hours, 8 minutes.
Lieutenant?
Special Emissary
K'Ehleyr has...
declared a short recess, sir.
I wish to run
a full diagnostic test
on all tactical
backup equipment.
We just ran a full test
on those systems.
I feel it necessary
to check them again.
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant,
I commend your diligence.
However, I'm concerned
that you're working
yourself too hard.
Sir, considering the unknown
elements we're about to face--
Lieutenant,
I order you to relax.
I am relaxed.
Yes, sir.
I've never before seen
the Lieutenant so unsettled.
The iceman's
finally melting.
( computer beeping )
( screeching )
( screechy grunts )
( growls )
( yells )
( screeching )
( panting )
It's not much of a program.
Computer.
( beeping )
Level Two.
( screeching )
( growling )
( trumpeting bellow )
( growls )
( grunting )
( trumpeting )
( bellowing yell )
( yells )
( grunts )
( sniffing )
( growls )
Some calisthenics programs
are better than others.
You still can make jokes?
You don't like people
with a sense of humor.
I did not say that.
Worf, you're
the perfect Klingon--
the ultimate minimalist.
Talk to me.
I've noted that some people
use humor as a shield.
They talk much, yet say little.
Whereas others
take a simpler approach.
Say nothing.
When one does not
have the words.
Or is loath to speak them.
( sighs )
Why didn't we do this
six years ago?
We were not ready.
I was.
No, we were both too young,
too unaware.
We lacked commitment.
Perhaps we lacked
courage as well.
No longer.
TlhIngan jiH.
Wait.
You can't mean--
We are mated.
Yes, I know.
I was there. But--
And now, we must solemnize
our union with the oath.
I am not going
to become your wife.
You already are.
Don't give me that
Klingon nonsense.
You would dishonor
our sacred traditions?
( scoffs )
They're not sacred.
They're absurd.
Marrying you
is out of the question
for a million reasons.
None of which
stopped you earlier.
Worf, it was what it was--
glorious and wonderful
and all that--
but it doesn't mean anything.
That is a human attitude.
I am human!
You are also Klingon.
So, that means
we should bond for life?
It is our way.
Yours.
Not mine.
TlhIngan jiH.
I will not take the oath.
Then this night
had no meaning,
and that I will not believe.
Believe what you will.
( holodeck doors
open and close )
Approaching
the coordinates.
Slow to impulse.
Short and long-range sensor
scans negative, Captain.
Lay in a standard
search pattern.
Search pattern
laid in.
Full impulse.
Engage.
I hope we find them before
they come out of their nap.
Agreed.
There's not an outpost
in this area
that could defend itself
from a Klingon warship.
I've been working
on our assignment,
trying a few
computer simulations.
Your devotion to duty
is commendable, if belated.
Unwilling to be alone with me?
I asked Commander Data
to help us analyze
the alternatives.
An android chaperone?
"Android," of course,
is correct,
but I fail to
see how "chaperone"
is applicable to
this situation.
Never mind.
I guess I can't blame you.
Tell me one thing.
You would have gone through
with the oath, wouldn't you?
Regardless of
the consequences
to our careers, to our lives?
Honor demanded no less.
What do you want?
Is honor all you
care about?
Don't you feel
anything else?
No comment, huh?
Poor android.
Whose behavior do you
find more perplexing,
human... or Klingon?
At the moment, I would
find it difficult to choose.
So would I.
Okay, when we locate the T'Ong,
there are two possibilities.
First...
We find the ship before it
reaches the awakening point.
In that case, we simply
keep the crew asleep.
Is that feasible?
We can beam an away team
over to the T'Ong and override
their cryogenic controls, sure.
That way, we simply
await the arrival
of the Klingon ship P'Rang.
So that when the
T'Ong's crew awakens,
they're surrounded
by their fellow Klingons.
That would be ideal.
But there's
the second possibility
that the crew of the T'Ong
has already revived.
They realize they're
in Federation territory,
and attack the nearest outpost.
They could have been
on a scientific voyage.
Klingons of that era doing
research for its own sake?
The point is,
they may be reasonable.
The point is that this is
beside the point.
These are Klingons
at war with us.
Whatever their mission was,
once they see a Federation
target, they'll attack.
Could the T'Ong be disabled
rather than destroyed?
We could probably knock out
their warp drive engines
without damaging
the rest of the ship.
That would gain you nothing.
Disable the ship,
and K'Temoc will
destroy it himself.
Klingons do not surrender.
If we don't reach the T'Ong
before its crew wakes up,
you have no alternatives.
I can't accept that.
There must be some way that we
can make the Klingons listen.
If we could only
convince them--
DATA:
Captain, we are detecting a ship
bearing 3-1-6, mark 4-2.
Extreme sensor range.
Lay an intercept course.
Go to Yellow Alert.
Shields are up.
Better lock in phasers.
This may be the
only chance you get.
Intercept course
laid in.
Hold this position.
Let's see if they've spotted us.
Magnification 100.
Mr. Data?
Sensors show
life-forms aboard,
but I am unable to ascertain
whether they are awake
or dormant.
However, their propulsion
system is inactive,
so I would hypothesize
that the crew is asleep.
( alarm blaring )
However, I could
be in error.
Shields holding.
They've cloaked themselves.
Well, Captain...
you've had your chance.
Transferring Engineering
to the Bridge.
Can you find them?
I think so.
Those old shields
weren't particularly efficient
at blocking gamma ray output.
If I can tune the sensors
to a particular band of...
There, got them.
Transferring
coordinates to helm.
Intercept, warp 2.
CLANCY:
Warp 2, sir.
Captain, let them die
like Klingons-- in battle.
They deserve that much.
Captain.
I have another option.
Captain's log,
stardate 42901.3.
Despite their cloaking shields,
we have located
the Klingon vessel T'Ong.
In an effort to avoid
further confrontation,
we're about to implement
the option
presented by Lieutenant Worf.
The T'Ong has
changed course
to 3-2, mark 8-1.
Increasing to warp 3.
Standard evasive maneuver.
Helm, stay with them.
Yes, sir.
The T'Ong is now
on a heading
of 4-2, mark 1-1-3.
They are accelerating
to warp 5.
They're gonna make
a break for it.
Mmm. Overtake.
Warp 8.
Aye.
Now, put us right
in their path
and come
to a full stop.
Full power to shields.
CREWMAN:
Full power, sir.
Well, we've thrown
down the gauntlet.
Let's see if
they pick it up.
They are slowing to impulse,
sir.
Phaser hit
on forward shields.
Firming up now, no damage.
I guess we've piqued
their interest now.
Agreed.
Let's give them a chance
to look their enemy
in the face.
Ready, Lieutenant?
WORF:
Open hailing frequencies.
CREWMAN:
Open, sir.
What?
What is this?
Captain K'Temoc, have
you lost your mind?
Halt your vessel
and drop your shields.
What treachery is this?
By whose authority?
I am Worf,
commanding the Enterprise,
and it is you who have committed
an act of treason
by firing on this vessel.
I have standing orders to fire
on all Federation ships.
You fool!
Did it not occur to you that
the war would be over by now?
I have no proof of that.
Trust your eyes.
Or is your brain still stuck
in its long slumber?
How do I know this is not
a Federation trick?
How can I be sure?
Captain, as you are
new to this century,
I have tried to be patient.
But I will tolerate
no further insubordination.
Drop your shields
immediately.
And if I refuse?
Then die in ignorance.
I can waste no more
time on you.
Phasers to full power.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
Phasers ready.
Target locked.
You dare not destroy us.
We are on a crucial mission
for the Klingon High Command.
Has the T'Ong
dropped its shields?
CREWMAN:
No, sir.
Very well, fire all phasers.
Wait!
Lower the shields.
I yield command of the T'Ong
to you, Captain Worf.
Long live the
Klingon Empire.
A wise decision, Captain.
Commander K'Ehleyr will board
your vessel and take command.
The Klingon cruiser
P'Rang will soon arrive
and escort you home.
And, Captain...
Yes?
Welcome to the 24th century.
I return command
of the ship to you, Captain.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Congratulations.
A very fine first command.
Well done.
How did you like command?
Comfortable chair.
And you wore it well.
One to beam aboard the T'Ong.
All set.
I relieve you.
But...
Yes, Lieutenant.
The Klingon vessel P'Rang
will rendezvous with you
in three days.
In the meantime,
I'll begin the assimilation
of these Klingons to our era.
Is there anything else
you require?
No.
Nothing else.
Damn you, Worf.
You'd let me go without saying
another word, wouldn't you?
What needs to be said?
Nothing. Everything.
We're about to go
our separate ways again.
And that disturbs you?
I hid the truth from you.
Last night did have meaning.
I was tempted to take
the oath with you.
That scared me.
I've never had such strong
feelings toward anyone.
Nor have I.
Then it was more
than just a point of honor.
Maybe someday,
when our paths cross again...
I won't be so easy
to get rid of.
K'Ehleyr...
I will not be complete
without you.
( console controls beep )