Captain's log,
Stardate 42923.4.
Despite misgivings
I have agreed
to Starfleet's request
that the Enterprise divert
to the Braslota system
to take part in
a war game exercise.
Joining us
as observer and mediator
is the Zakdorn master
strategist, Sirna Kolrami.
Mr. Kolrami.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
Welcome aboard.
Captain, I bring you greetings
from those at Starfleet Command.
Would you care to be
shown to your quarters?
I require little
rest, Captain.
I prefer that we commence
with our mission.
Despite their reputations,
this Zakdorn
does not appear to be
a very formidable warrior.
In the game of
military brinksmanship
individual physical prowess
is less important
than the perception
of a species as a whole.
For over nine millennia
potential foes have
regarded the Zakdorns
as having the greatest innately
strategic minds in the galaxy.
So no one is willing to test
that perception in combat.
Exactly.
Then the reputation
means nothing.
The Braslota system.
In orbit around
the second planet
is the 80-year-old
Starcruiser Hathaway.
He is still your first choice?
Commander Riker will
captain the Hathaway.
You will have 48 hours
to ready your vessel
before the Enterprise
attacks.
And we'll experience
actual battle conditions?
Correct.
Engineering will disconnect
the Enterprise's weapons
and link the system with
a modified laser pulse beam.
All hits will
be recorded
electronically.
If the computer
registers damage,
it will act accordingly
shutting down
the affected areas
for the appropriate
repair time.
Additional questions?
Captain Picard,
it is my understanding
that you initially resisted
Starfleet's request
for this simulation.
Yes.
May I know why?
Starfleet is not
a military organization.
Its purpose is exploration.
Then why am I here?
With the Borg threat
I decided that my officers
and I needed...
to hone our
tactical skills.
In a crisis situation
it is prudent to have
several options.
Ah.
RIKER:
I prefer brains
over brawn, as well.
I think it's a waste of effort
to test our combat skills.
It's a minor province in the
makeup of a starship captain.
Your objection is noted.
Let us hope that your
distaste for the exercise
will not affect
your strategic abilities.
Mr. Kolrami, when I agree
to do something,
I do it.
Would you care
to surrender now, Captain?
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out
new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
Well, Number One, you are
allowed a complement of 40
so select whom you will.
Save, of course,
Mr. Data
who will serve
as my First Officer
during your absence.
I had envisioned you
defining the crew.
On my ship,
the leader of an away team
has total control
of the mission.
If you want to judge leadership,
why not start at the beginning?
Very well
Captain.
Hmm.
Oh, my.
What a charmer.
Doctor.
Captain, he needs
an attitude adjustment.
The Zakdornian culture
is replete
with self-assuredness
and confidence.
Seldom is it undeserved.
For example, Kolrami is
a third-level grand master
at the game of Strategema.
Another millimeter.
That's it.
A little more.
There.
That's excellent.
RIKER:
Lieutenant.
Yes, Commander.
You've heard about the
simulation aboard the Hathaway?
Oh, yes, sir, and the
best of luck to you.
I've researched those
old Avidyne engines.
They're archaic by our
standards, very touchy.
Anticipating the worst
do you think they can be whipped
into shape in 48 hours?
I've already
taken the liberty
of putting together
a few necessities.
( door chime )
Enter!
Am I disturbing you?
Just finished.
You know of the simulation,
what do you think?
Waste of time.
It's just designed
to be an exercise.
Useless.
If there is nothing
to lose, no sacrifice
then there is nothing to gain.
You mean besides pride.
Well, in this case,
it doesn't matter.
I probably haven't
got a chance.
There is always a chance.
Slim.
The Hathaway's most
sophisticated weapons system--
even in a computer mock-up--
can't hope to defeat
the Enterprise.
Well, still...
You're outmanned, you're
outgunned, you're out-equipped.
What else have you got?
Guile.
Join me.
The honor is to serve.
PICARD:
Begin long-range scanning
of all sectors
within three light-years
of Braslota.
How's your crew shaping up?
It's complete,
but I would like
to request an addition.
Anyone in particular?
With your permission
I would like
acting Ensign Crusher on board
for educational
observation.
Thank you, Captain.
It appears we'll
have some time
before reaching Braslota.
I was wondering
if you'd agree
to play me
in a game of Strategema.
Although I'm intrigued
by the audacity of your request
I can't fathom why you would
wish the encounter.
I enjoy a challenge.
Very well.
An opponent of limited
dimensions
can often be quite diverting.
Thank you.
So you're going to beat him,
huh?
No.
Well, then it's going
to be a close one?
Nope.
But you have got a chance?
Nah.
Are you even going
to bother to show up?
Sure, Kolrami
is the best ever
at Strategema.
Just to get to play
him is a privilege.
So, aside from
your being privileged
is there anything else
I can look forward to?
Nope.
This is going
to be exciting.
Against an opponent
of approximate skill
Strategema can last
well over 1,000 moves.
I wouldn't bet on us
being here that long.
I have wagered heavily
in the ship's pool
that you will take him
past the sixth plateau.
And if I don't?
I will be... irritated.
Forever curious,
this urge to compete.
It's a human response.
That inborn craving
to gauge your capabilities
through conflict.
Doctor, there are other ways
to challenge oneself.
Well, perhaps, but they all lack
a certain thrill.
Data, humans sometimes
find it helpful
to have an outsider
set the standard
by which
they're judged.
To avoid deceiving oneself.
Maybe you should challenge
Kolrami to Strategema.
Why, Doctor?
Because, when
someone is that smug
you occasionally
have to deflate
them, just a little.
Yeah, Data.
I'd like to see
your neural flecks
tear him down a peg.
To what end?
WORF:
Computer...
actuation positions
for Strategema.
Ready?
Begin.
LA FORGE:
Come on, Commander.
Come on now.
You can do it.
You can get him.
Come on, Commander,
come on.
You got him, you got him.
Watch him now.
( observers encouraging
and commenting )
( computer beeps )
Hmm.
That's it?
I'm afraid so.
But you only
made 23 moves.
Yes.
Congratulations.
Hmm, hmm-hmm.
Commander Riker,
there's your
next challenge.
WORF:
Away team assembled and ready
to transport, Commander.
I may get over there
and want to come right home.
Good luck, Number One...
Captain.
The simulation will
commence in 48 hours.
LA FORGE:
There should be some
emergency bridge lighting here.
( beeping )
( whirring )
Not good.
Ah, you're
wrong, Mr. Worf.
It's fantastic.
And it's ours.
Mr. Worf.
Sir...
Lieutenant La Forge
is a superior officer.
The honor
should be his.
Worf, this is
a battle simulation.
You're my tactical officer.
Discussed this with Geordi,
and we agreed.
I need you by my side.
LA FORGE:
Besides, Worf,
if Engineering
is anything like the Bridge
I'm going to have
my hands full.
( ship's whistle sounds )
Attention crew
of the USS Hathaway.
This is your Captain.
Over the next two days,
you might lose
a lot of sleep
but with your skill
and your stamina
we'll have this
old lady ready to fly.
I want hourly progress reports
from all stations.
Riker out.
( generators coming on-line )
( engines powering up )
Nice job, Geordi.
Now what are the possibilities
of warp drive?
Hmm...
not good.
There are only a few
dilithium fragments left
in the holding clamps.
Even if we had crystals
that were intact
there's no antimatter
to fuel the drive.
RIKER:
Any recommendations?
No, sir.
We haven't got a prayer.
Would you like
to transfer back
to the Enterprise,
Mr. Crusher?
No, sir.
Wes, remember our purpose
is to improvise.
It's the effort that counts.
Open.
I believe the rules
are understood by all.
Weapons conversion,
Lieutenant Burke?
Complete, Captain.
Signal received.
Locked on.
She's really been
stripped down, Captain.
The only offensive
systems you'll need
will be simulated
by computer.
What's the Zakdornian word
for mismatch?
Challenge.
We do not whine
about the inequities of life.
And how you perform
in a mismatch
is precisely what is of interest
to Starfleet.
After all, when one is
in the superior position
one is expected to win.
Screen off.
You have the Bridge, Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant Commander
Data, I'm intrigued
by your challenge.
Dr. Pulaski informed
me of your desire
to play a game
of Strategema.
But I expressed
no such interest.
What Commander Data
means is that
he would never have
asked you himself.
But I know that he's
very interested
in pitting his skill
against yours.
Play against a machine.
Hmm.
Why should I wish to?
I don't blame you.
It's no fun
going into a game
when you know
you're going to lose.
But I wouldn't lose.
Now you're no doubt
going to tell me
that I have to prove it to you.
Come on, Data, you
can't let that pass.
Indeed, I...
( inaudible )
Cannot.
Then you will play
for the honor of your ship.
Hmm, hmm-hmm.
The honor of the ship?
It's your reputation
that's on the line.
With my knowledge
of the Enterprise's
security override
we may be able
to convince the sensors
that an enemy ship
is approaching.
Their instruments
would... lie to them.
If you can pull
that off, Mr. Worf
you might give us the
edge we're looking for.
But what about the viewscreen?
If I am successful,
the computer will project
a false image of the enemy ship
on the main viewscreen.
So unless someone runs
to a window and looks out...
They're going to fall for it.
The lining's still smooth.
We should be able
to do something
with these dilithium
fragments we scavenged.
Sure, the system's functional
but, without antimatter,
what difference does it make?
Geordi, I have to return
to the Enterprise.
Wes, we've
only got 32 hours.
This is important.
And this isn't?
Attempt the routing
bypass here.
If it works, they
will be surprised.
Where I'm I going to get
the opti-cable?
Anywhere.
Captain.
I left an experiment running
back on the Enterprise.
May I go back
and shut it down?
It's that important?
Well, it has
to be monitored.
And it is my final grade
in plasma physics.
Message from the Hathaway, sir.
On screen.
RIKER:
Request permission
for Ensign Crusher
to reboard the Enterprise.
Why?
Apparently, he was so anxious
to join the away team
he left a very critical
experiment unattended.
Do you have
any objection?
He should be escorted
and have no contact
with anything
save his research.
Permission granted.
Mr. Burke, will you handle that?
Aye, sir.
I saw no sense
in Riker choosing him anyway.
He's just
a noncommissioned child.
I can't believe
I forgot about this.
It's a good lesson
not to let excitement
cloud your judgment.
Yeah.
This is very delicate.
I spent six weeks
setting this up.
That's a lot of work.
Oh, no.
This is ruined.
That's too bad.
Look, uh, is this going
to take much longer?
I'm going to have to
dispose of this safely.
This is very volatile.
I'll beam it
off the Enterprise
and leave it
particalized.
That's fine.
Let's just do it.
All right, I'll transfer
the coordinates
to the Transporter Room.
( clinks )
( inaudible whisper )
In the present context
what did she mean
by "bust him up"?
In her own way
Dr. Pulaski was
instructing you to take
the shortest route
to victory.
As opposed to what?
Ready?
Begin.
( observers calling out
encouragement )
WOMAN:
Good, good.
MAN:
Oh, look at them.
Good, Data.
WOMAN:
Oh...
MAN:
Harder, harder.
WOMAN:
Look.
MAN:
Watch it, watch it.
WOMAN:
One more, one more.
There.
MAN:
Come on.
( computer beeps )
I can't believe it.
A computer beaten
by flesh and blood?
( hissing )
You advanced quite far
against such a worthy opponent.
Thoroughly
enjoyable, Mr. Data.
I'm at your disposal
for a rematch.
Thank you,
but what would be the point?
Hmm, hmm-hmm.
How can you lose?
You're supposed
to be infallible.
Obviously, I am not.
Ensign, where is
Commander Data?
He has temporarily removed
himself from Bridge duty, sir.
Your crew is excellently
trained, Captain.
A tribute to your leadership.
Although I doubt
their extensive preparation
will be needed.
Why is that?
I do not expect
"Captain" Riker
will present
much of a challenge.
Mr. Kolrami, may I speak
with you in private?
I would like to know the
root of your prejudice
for my First Officer.
Oh, Captain, I don't...
Mr. Kolrami, you
have been nothing
but denigrating and abusive
of Commander Riker
since coming
aboard this ship.
Now, I would like
some explanation.
Having studied
William Riker's file
prior to this assignment
I have found
him... wanting.
In what regard?
His work record
is exemplary.
But, as you know
a Starship Captain
is not manufactured.
He or she is born
from-from inside
from the character
of the individual.
My interviews
have revealed a man
who displays
circumstantially
inappropriate joviality
belying the seriousness
of his station.
Don't confuse style with intent.
Only a fool would question
Commander Riker's dedication
to Starfleet
and the men and women
under his command.
He is simply the finest officer
with whom I have ever served.
We shall see
if your faith
is well-founded.
The test is whether
the crew will follow
where Commander Riker leads.
His...
His joviality is the means
by which he creates
that loyalty.
And I will match
his command style
with your statistics anytime.
Hmm.
( door chime )
Come in, please.
Data.
Counselor
is something the matter?
That was going to be
my question.
With my repository of knowledge
I expected to perform better
against a humanoid life-form.
You know,
some of our greatest advances
have come
from analyzing failure.
While it can be
ego-bruising...
But, Counselor,
I do not have an ego.
Yes.
Well, um... a loss
can be disheartening...
But, Counselor,
I do not have a...
Data.
You can handle defeat
in two ways.
You can lose confidence
or you can learn
from your mistakes.
That is what troubles me.
I made no mistakes.
I have conducted
a diagnostic check
of all of my programs.
I'm now cross-checking
with the ship's computer.
Is that all
necessary?
I believe so.
I have proven to be vulnerable.
At the present time,
my deductions should be
treated with skepticism.
So, that's why you haven't
been on the Bridge.
Yes.
The Captain would be ill-advised
to rely upon my judgment.
I think you're overreacting.
I'm sure you're all right.
I, however, am not sure.
Easy now.
Is that it?
Yeah.
Good work.
All right.
Hand me that connector
on the kit.
RIKER:
What is that?
My experiment
from the Enterprise.
Wes.
It deals with high-energy
plasma reactions
with antimatter.
You went back
to the Enterprise for that?
Wes, you cheated.
No, sir.
You told me to improvise.
LA FORGE:
The hard part is going
to be calibrating
the thermal curve necessary
to start
a controlled reaction.
Assuming you can,
can you regulate the reaction?
There's just enough crystal
left to do it.
We plan to channel the reaction
through the chips.
Are we good?
You're better than good.
Great, brilliant.
It's going to be fun.
Carry on.
( door chime )
Come in, please.
All right, Data,
enough of this.
Doctor?
How long are you going
to sit sulking
like Achilles in his tent?
I'm conducting diagnostic...
You may be able to sell
Troi that story
but not me.
Now, you're smarting
because you were beaten.
Well, it happens.
No, Doctor, this
is not about ego.
I am concerned about giving
the Captain unsound advice.
I wish I had never maneuvered
you into playing that game.
I'm sorry.
Why, Doctor?
It is done,
and perhaps just as well.
This has indicated that I am
damaged in some fashion.
I must find the malfunction.
RIKER:
The simulation begins
in one hour.
You'll have warp
drive, Captain
though it may not be
what you expected.
I think that deserves
some kind of explanation.
We'll have warp 1
for about...
Just under two seconds.
That's not long enough
or an escape
but, used as a surprise
it may give
a strategic advantage.
Sir, all of this
is theoretical.
And if your theory
fails to pay off?
Have you ever driven
a Grenthemen water hopper?
Sure.
Ever popped the clutch?
You're saying we're going
to stall the Hathaway?
And the Enterprise
will waltz right over
and pulverize us.
Now, let me try to understand.
You're saying
that Commander Data
is suffering from
a profound
loss of confidence
and that you believe
that only I can
restore the balance?
Yes, sir.
Both Deanna
and I have tried
but we're not getting
through to him.
Don't you think you both might
be overreacting?
Data is not capable
of the emotions
which you're assigning him.
The effects are the same
whether they're caused
by human emotions
or android algorithms.
Data's not on the Bridge,
and I don't think
Data's going to be
on the Bridge
until we find some way
to address his problem.
I'm less than one hour away
from a battle simulation
and I have to handhold
an android.
The burdens of command.
( door chime )
Come in, please.
Commander, I require
your presence on the Bridge.
Captain, with
all due respect
perhaps it would be better
if you choose another
to serve as your First Officer.
Data, you are
my First Officer.
I have not been able
to isolate the problem, sir.
I might make a mistake.
Yes, you might
but that does not alter your
duty to me and to this ship.
Now, do you know
how to formulate a premise?
Yes, sir.
Then formulate this one.
How do I deal with Commander
Riker and the Hathaway?
I will await your answer
on the Bridge.
And, Commander...
it is possible
to commit no mistakes
and still lose.
That is not
a weakness.
That is life.
I believe I understand, sir.
And, Data, will you leave
your hesitation and self-doubt
here in your quarters.
I have several examples
of Commander Riker's
battle technique.
At the Academy, he calculated
a sensory blind spot
on a Tholian vessel
and hid within it
during a battle
simulation.
And, as a Lieutenant
aboard the Potemkin
his solution to a crisis
was to shut down all power
and hang over a planet's
magnetic poles
thus confusing
his opponent's sensors.
And from these specifics
what general conclusion
can you extrapolate?
Only 21% of the time
does he rely
on traditional tactics.
So...
the Captain must be prepared
for unusual cunning.
Counselor, Commander Riker
will assume
we have made this analysis
and knowing
that we know his methods
he will alter them.
But knowing that he knows
that we know that he knows
he might choose to return
to his usual pattern.
Wait, wait, you're
overanalyzing, Data.
One cannot deny human nature.
What kind of a man
is Commander Riker?
A fighter?
Yes.
The weaker his position
the more aggressive
will be his posture.
And he won't give up.
Then, despite whatever
options he is given
he must be...
The man that he is.
Exactly.
Is that a failing in humans?
You'll have to decide that
for yourself.
On screen.
The hunt begins, Number One.
We're ready.
Just remember, Enterprise
Captain Riker's never lost.
KOLRAMI:
Begin now.
Screen off.
Set course 2-2-3 mark 3-5-7,
full impulse power.
Initiate Kumeh maneuver.
Kumeh maneuver?
Why would they start out
with such a recognizable ploy?
He's teasing.
He wants us to reveal
our tactics on his terms.
Mr. Worf?
Counter with
the Talupian maneuver
on instrument sighting.
Agreed.
Three-quarter impulse,
full on my command.
Ensign Nagel, maximum shields.
Mr. Worf, prepare
your little surprise.
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Set course 3-1-7 mark 7-3.
Present minimal aspect.
Ready warp 1.
Optimal spread
on simulated torpedoes.
BURKE:
Captain
Romulan warship approaching
fast from astern.
What the...
He came out of nowhere, sir.
Bring us about, Ensign.
Maximum shields.
( alarm sounding )
Full weapon systems.
DATA:
Disengage...
Lock on, open a
hailing frequency.
I can't, sir.
There's nothing there.
( loud electronic beeps )
Warp 3, evasive.
Stand by.
Disengage weapons and shields.
Reengage modified beam.
He's quite good.
He's the best.
Computer reports
simulated damage
to several aft decks, sir.
Repair time 3.6 Days.
How did he do that?
Mr. Worf must have overridden
the sensor codes
played some
holographic games.
Mr. Data, input a new code.
Attack posture,
circumvental attitude.
Prepare beams for photon mode.
( quietly):
Bye-bye, Hathaway.
Computers report heavy damage
to the Enterprise.
WESLEY:
They're moving off, sir.
Why not go after them?
Because they're not through
coming after us.
Wesley, Geordi,
prepare to warp jump.
There are no
guarantees here, sir.
There never are, Lieutenant.
I'm going to trust your
expertise.
Secure your stations.
Stand by for my signal.
Ready the photon torpedoes.
Captain, sensors picking up
a Ferengi warship
closing
at warp 5.
Did you input that new code?
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, I didn't give you
enough credit.
Continue the simulation.
Divert all power to shields.
Sever modified beams.
Stay between the Ferengi
and the Hathaway.
Engage phasers
and target.
PICARD:
Fire when ready.
That's no ghost attacking
the Enterprise.
That's real.
We must assist, sir.
With what?
We have no
offensive weapons.
Where are my weapons?
BURKE:
Unavailable, sir.
We cannot disengage
the modified beams.
The connections have been fused.
We must retreat.
Unacceptable.
The Ferengi have broken off
their attack.
Drop shields, transport
the away team aboard.
Transporter functions gone, sir.
Shields reduced
to 1/5 intensity.
Use their moment of
indecision to escape.
I have 40 crew members
onboard the Hathaway...
Who should be sacrificed
to save a thousand.
Acceptable tactical losses,
considering the circumstances.
Not to me.
Notify Starfleet,
priority.
Hail the Ferengi on my command.
Formulate alternatives.
As the Starfleet
observer
I am ordering
you to withdraw.
I am the Captain of this vessel.
Your order is nullified.
Ferengi on main viewscreen.
I am Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation Starship
USS Enterprise.
Why have you attacked my vessel?
Why was your ship combative
with another Federation vessel
of lesser design?
Why do you now protect
your former target?
What is its value to you?
Our probes indicate
you were aware
of our approach,
yet took no action.
Your answers will dictate
our response.
We have refrained
from launching a counterattack
in the hope that this
can be resolved peacefully.
Our probes indicate
that you are crippled
and the ship you protect
has no weaponry
no light-speed drive
and only a scarce crew.
This makes no
sense to us.
Unless it contains
something very valuable.
I am Bractor,
leader of the Ferengi
attack vessel Kreechta.
I will have the secret
of the other
Federation ship.
Surrender it to me
and I will allow
your Enterprise
to leave unharmed.
You have ten of your minutes.
Sir, they're massing
a surge of power.
We're being scanned.
They've locked on.
Data?
Our shields will not withstand
another assault, sir.
Then there are no options.
Retreat...
or die.
Captain's log, supplemental.
Due to a miscalculation
on my part
the Enterprise
has been subjected
to a surprise attack
by the Ferengi.
I find myself with little time
to decide the fate
of 40 of my crew stranded
aboard the derelict Hathaway.
I am open
to suggestions.
Captain, we are now capable
of launching
a limited number
of photon torpedoes.
I've already given you
my advice, Captain.
The Hathaway
is expendable.
Commander Riker
is hailing, sir.
On screen.
Number One, have you been
monitoring communications?
Yes, sir.
Kolrami's right.
You've got to save
the Enterprise.
That would leave you
defenseless.
When Bractor closes in,
we'll hit our warp drive.
Take our chances.
Your what?
We have a limited
two-second warp capability.
Impossible! That ship was
rendered warp inactive.
I told you
he was the best.
I'd like to hear more
about this, Number One, later.
Right now, I have to work
something out with Mr. Data.
Premise-- the Ferengi wish
to capture the Hathaway
believing it to be of value.
Therefore, we must remove
the ship
from their field of interest.
And they will soon relocate it
after a two second warp...
There is a way.
Number One, can
you hear this?
Yes, sir, we're all here.
Waiting for you to
pull another rabbit
out of your hat.
Mr. Data?
On the Captain's command
we will fire
four photon torpedoes
directly at the Hathaway.
One millisecond
after its detonation
the computer will trigger
your warp jump.
I think I hate this plan.
Data, we're not even sure
our warp jump will work.
If the warp engines
fail to function
the result could be...
unfortunate.
WORF:
Very unfortunate.
We will be dead.
PICARD:
Captain Riker
I cannot order you to do this.
What the hell,
nobody said life was safe.
The advantage is
that it will appear
from the Kreechta's perspective
as though...
as though you were destroyed
in the explosion.
That will deceive them
only for a few minutes.
Their sensors
will soon locate us.
We'll only need a few minutes,
Mr. Worf
because you're going to prepare
another surprise for them.
PICARD:
Then we're agreed.
On my mark, four minutes.
DATA:
Remember, Geordi...
if the implementation
is off by one millisecond
the Hathaway will not survive.
Data, that's the one part
of this plan
that we're all
absolutely sure about.
Are we ready, Number One?
Ready, Captain.
Good luck to both of you.
Bractor.
I will wait
no longer, Picard.
You needn't.
The answer is no.
Your actions
have been wholly criminal.
You will not profit by them.
You are a fool.
How can you stop us?
You believe
the Hathaway has value?
We deny you your prize.
Fire.
Destroy your own
rather than suffer
the ignominy of defeat
and capture?
I did not think
the Federation
had such iron.
You had no claim on that vessel.
It was ours to destroy.
As you
are ours to destroy.
You can try.
Enterprise
targeted, Leader.
Leader, there is another
Federation ship closing.
A starship.
Maximum shields.
We have been outmaneuvered.
Retreat.
Captain, our sensors
show no Federation
starship nearby.
RIKER:
Of course not, Mr. Burke.
That was Klingon guile.
You made it, Number One.
Smooth ride?
Well, it certainly
was different.
We'll lock on and pick you up.
With pleasure, Captain.
Uh...
I must admit,
your Commander Riker
acquitted himself
quite admirably.
And so, Captain
have you.
My report
to Starfleet
will be most favorable.
Thank you.
Hmm, hmm-hmm.
Initiate recovery procedures.
Continue repairs.
Plot a course
for the nearest Starbase.
Captain's log, supplemental.
With the transporter repaired
and my crew safely back aboard
we have officially ended
our first Starfleet
battle simulation.
( excited voices
in the distance )
Come on, come on.
Don't lose it.
Come on.
You've got him.
Come on, Data.
Come on.
( encouragement continues )
( exclamation of disgust )
Why have you suspended the game?
Because this
is not a rematch.
You have made a mockery of me.
Data, you beat him.
No, sir, it is a stalemate.
No game of Strategema
has ever gone this high.
What did
you do?
I simply altered my premise
for playing the game.
Explain.
Working under the assumption
that Kolrami
was attempting to win
it is reasonable to assume
that he expected me
to play for the same goal.
You didn't.
No, I was playing
for a standoff.
A draw.
While Kolrami
was dedicated to winning
I was able to pass up
obvious avenues of advancement
and settle for a balance.
Theoretically, I should be able
to challenge him indefinitely.
Then you have beaten him.
It is a matter of perspective,
Doctor.
In the strictest sense,
I did not win.
Data.
I busted him up.
( all cheering )
♪♪